(Footsteps walking)
(Door opens, closes)
(Walking footsteps)
-(Glass clinking)
-(Liquid pouring)
(Tape rewinding)
(Tape recorder clicks off)
Man (Recorded voice):
What is the cost of lies?
It's not that we'll mistake
them for the truth.
The real danger is that
if we hear enough lies,
then we no longer
recognize the truth at all.
What can we do then?
What else is left
but to abandon even
the hope of truth
and content
ourselves instead
with stories?
In these stories,
it doesn't matter
who the heroes are.
All we want to know is:
who is to blame?
In this story,
it was Anatoly Dyatlov.
He was the best choice.
An arrogant, unpleasant man,
he ran the room that night,
he gave the orders...
and no friends.
Or, at least,
not important ones.
And now Dyatlov will spend
the next ten years
in a prison labor camp.
Of course, that sentence
is doubly unfair.
There were far greater
criminals than him at work.
And as for what Dyatlov did do,
the man doesn't deserve prison.
He deserves death.
(Recorder clicks)
(Clears throat)
But instead, ten years
for "criminal mismanagement."
What does that mean?
No one knows.
It doesn't matter.
What does matter
is that, to them,
justice was done.
Because, you see, to them
a just world is a sane world.
There was nothing sane
about Chernobyl.
What happened there,
what happened after,
even the good we did,
all of it...
all of it... madness.
Well, I've given you
everything I know.
They'll deny it, of course.
They always do.
I know you'll try your best.
(Tape rewinding)
♪ ♪
(Sighs)
(Door opens, closes)
(Ticking)
♪ ♪
(Furniture scraping floor)
(Ticking)
(Furniture clatters)
(Rope creaking)
(Woman vomits, coughs)
(Woman groans, pants)
(Toilet flushing)
(Snoring softly)
-(Distant explosion)
-(Gasps)
Man:
Lyudmilla?
(Dogs barking outside)
♪ ♪
(Barking continuing)
(Debris swishing)
Man (Distant, muffled voice):
Comrade Dyatlov!
♪ ♪
(Shouting):
Comrade Dyatlov!
-(Alarms blaring)
-What just happened?
-I don't know.
-(Alarms blaring, buzzing)
There's a fire
in the turbine hall.
The turbine hall.
The control system tank.
Hydrogen.
You and Toptunov,
you morons blew the tank!
-No, that's not--
-This is an emergency.
Everyone stay calm.
Our first priority is--
-It's exploded!
-We know.
Akimov, are we cooling
the reactor core?
We shut it down,
but the control rods
are still active.
They're not all the way in,
I disengaged the clutch.
Try and disconnect the servos
from the standby console.
You two, get
the backup pumps running.
We need water moving
through the core.
-That is all that matters.
-There is no core.
It exploded,
the core exploded.
(Alarms blaring, buzzing)
He's in shock.
Get him out of here.
The lid is off!
The stack is burning.
I saw it.
You're confused.
RBMK reactor cores
don't explode.
-Akimov...
-(Whispers): Sasha.
Don't worry,
we did everything right.
Something...
something strange has happened.
-Do you taste metal?
-Akimov!
Comrade Perevozschenko,
what you're saying is
physically impossible.
The core can't explode.
It has to be the tank.
We're wasting time.
Let's go.
Get the hydrogen
out of the generators
and pump water into the core.
-What about the fire?
-Call the fire brigade.
(Alarms blaring, buzzing)
(Distant alarm blaring)
(Footsteps crunching glass)
(Wind whistling)
♪ ♪
(Distant alarms
continue blaring)
♪ ♪
(Loud tone drones)
(Voices over phone
speaking Russian)
(Loud tone drones)
You're not on call tonight.
Man:
They're bringing everybody in,
military and civil.
Pripyat, Polesskoe, Kiev.
This is a big one.
But it doesn't look right,
the color.
Pravik says
he thinks they're shining
floodlights or something.
And what if
there are chemicals?
(Chuckles):
Chemicals?
The problem's the roof.
It's covered in tar,
so it's gonna burn all night,
and it'll stink like hell.
That's it.
That's the worst of it.
Go back to bed.
(Door opens, closes)
(Alarms blaring)
(Muffled clattering above)
-Is it war?
-Where's the dosimeter?
Here... Here.
(Debris clattering)
Are they bombing?
(Dosimeter beeps)
What the fuck is this?
It's 3.6 roentgen.
That's as high as it goes.
The good one's locked in a safe.
I don't have a key.
Valera... your face.
Come on.
I'm going to find Khodemchuk
in the pump room.
You... here.
Get Shashenok.
He's in 604. Go.
We need to get
everyone out!
(Alarm blaring)
(Vomits, coughing)
(Whimpers)
Shit.
Hey! We need to get
to the reactor hall.
-The lift's destroyed.
-Up two flights and across.
-Right.
-Why are you going there?
(Distant alarm blaring)
(Clangs echoing)
-(Clangs)
-(Grunts)
Have you seen
Khodemchuk?
-No. Where's Viktor?
-Still in the pump room.
-(Perevozschenko vomits)
-Stay here. I'll come back.
Viktor!
(Man coughing)
Viktor.
-(Coughing)
-Viktor.
Viktor. I'm gonna get
you out of here.
-Can you stand?
-(Coughs)
(Weakly):
Khodemchuk...
Where?
Viktor (Gasping):
Get Khodemchuk.
(Fluttering)
(Metal groaning)
(Gasping)
(Distant sirens approaching)
(Alarms blaring, buzzing)
I dropped the control rods
from the other panel.
-Akimov: They're still up.
-Dyatlov: What?
They're still only
a third of the way in,
I don't know why.
I already sent the trainees
down to the reactor hall
to lower them by hand.
-What about the pumps?
-Toptunov: I can't get
through to Khodemchuk.
-The lines are down.
-Fuck the phones
and fuck Khodemchuk.
-Are the pumps on or not?
-Stolyarchuk?
My control panel's
not working.
I tried calling
for the electricians.
I don't give a shit
about the panel!
I need water in my reactor core!
Get down there and make sure
those pumps are on.
Now!
-What does the dosimeter say?
-3.6 roentgen, but that's
as high as the meter--
3.6-- not great,
not terrible.
(In undertone):
We did everything right.
(Sirens wailing)
(Indistinct radio transmissions)
(Indistinct shouting)
Commander:
You, connect those hooks!
(Men shouting)
Commander:
Get the pumps going!
Man:
Yeah, over here!
-(Alarms blaring)
-Man: We're working
bottom to top. Go in fast.
♪ ♪
Vasily...
-Hey, Vasily, what's this?
-I don't know, Misha.
Don't fuck around with it.
Hook these up, come on.
Do you taste metal?
-Yeah, what is that?
-I don't know.
The valves, Misha!
The valves, let's go!
The valves! Come on!
(Sirens wailing)
(Footsteps echoing)
(Distant siren wailing)
What do you need?
We need to get
into the reactor hall
to lower the control rods,
but the door is jammed.
I don't think there are
control rods.
I don't think there's a core.
No, you're--
you're mistaken.
Akimov said.
Let's go.
(Misha wailing): No!
-(Misha screaming)
-Ignatenko, get on his hose!
It's all right. Breathe.
-(Misha whimpering)
-Misha.
All right, all right.
Easy, Misha.
(Grunts)
(Groaning)
♪ ♪
(Alarms buzzing)
Are you sure?
Akimov...
-(Men grunting)
-(Metal scraping)
Move.
(Grunting)
Come on, go!
(Grunts, speaks indistinctly)
(Grunts, panting)
(Door creaking)
♪ ♪
(Grunts)
Let's go!
Hey!
(Gasps)
(Groans)
Hey!
(Alarm buzzing)
(Panting)
(People chattering)
(Distant sirens wailing)
Woman:
Lyudmilla! Do you
want to come with us?
Come where?
We're going to the railroad
bridge to get a better look.
It's not like anyone
can sleep with all the sirens.
I don't think you should go.
It could be dangerous.
What do you mean dangerous?
It's a fire. It's over there,
we're over here.
-Mikhail.
-What?
Oh, sorry.
Oh.
-Oksana: Is Vasily...?
-Yeah.
Did he say it was bad?
No. No, he said it was
just the roof.
Well, he's never
gotten hurt before.
None of the boys have.
He'll be fine.
Get some rest.
(Distant sirens continuing)
Dyatlov:
The tank,
it's big enough.
This kind of explosion,
the control tank on 71,
it's 100 cubic meters.
One hundred and ten.
Hundred and ten.
It could do this, definitely.
(Panting):
It's gone.
I looked right into it.
I looked into the core.
Did you lower
the control rods or not?
(Retching)
Take him
to the infirmary.
Toptunov, take him!
-Where's Kudryavstev?
-He fell.
-Toptunov:
I need a medic! Anyone!
-He's delusional.
-His face...
-Ruptured condenser lines.
The feedwater is
mildly contaminated.
He'll be fine.
I've seen worse.
Do we still have
a phone line to the outside?
-Akimov?
-(Grunts)
Call in the day shift.
-But if the--
-We have to keep water
flowing into the core.
We need electricians,
mechanics, we need bodies.
How many times
do I have to say it?
I'm going to
the Administration Building now
to call Bryukhanov and Fomin.
They're gonna want
a full report.
Now, I don't know if I can
make things better for you,
but I can certainly
make them worse.
Call in the day shift,
Comrade Akimov.
Yes, Comrade Dyatlov.
(Sighs)
(Door closes)
-(Woman moans softly)
-You're doing fine.
Raise her up.
That one,
maybe an hour.
This one,
not until morning.
-How's it
downstairs, doctor?
-Quiet.
Always is.
Nothing at this hour
but babies.
You know, I once went
two days without sleep?
Ten women went into labor
at the same time.
-Did I ever tell
you that story?
-Yes.
Well, I won't need you
in here for a while.
If you want, get some rest
in the break room.
They haven't brought
anyone in from the fire.
-What fire?
-The power plant.
Oh. Then it
mustn't be too bad.
Do we stock iodine?
-Hmm?
-Iodine.
-You mean disinfectant?
-No, pills. Does the hospital
stock iodine pills?
Iodine pills?
Why would we have
iodine pills?
(Phone rings)
Hello?
(Coughing)
Who else knows this?
Have you called Fomin?
Of course I want you
to call him.
If I'm up, he's up.
♪ ♪
(Sirens wailing)
Fomin:
Whatever the cause,
the important thing is
that neither you nor I--
♪ ♪
(Heavy door thudding)
I take it the safety test
was a failure?
-We have the situation
under control.
-Fomin: Under control?
-It doesn't look like
it's under control.
-Shut up, Fomin.
I have to tell the Central
Committee about this.
Do you realize that?
I have to get on the phone
and tell Maryin,
or God forbid Frolyshev,
that my power plant
is on fire.
No one can blame you for this,
Director Bryukhanov.
Of course no one can
blame me for this.
How can I be responsible?
I was sleeping.
Tell me what happened,
quickly.
We ran the test exactly as
Chief Engineer Fomin approved.
Unit Shift Chief Akimov
and Engineer Toptunov
encountered technical
difficulties leading
to an accumulation of hydrogen
in the control system tank.
It regrettably ignited,
damaging the plant,
setting the roof on fire.
The tank is quite large.
It's the only
logical explanation.
Of course, Deputy Chief
Engineer Dyatlov
was directly
supervising the test,
so he would know best.
-Bryukhanov:
A hydrogen tank, fire...
-(Pen scribbling)
-Reactor?
-We're taking
measures to ensure
a steady flow of water
through the core.
-What about radiation?
-Obviously, down here
it's nothing.
But in the reactor building,
I'm being told
3.6 roentgen per hour.
Well, that's not great,
but it's not horrifying.
Not at all.
-From the feedwater,
I assume?
-Mm-hmm.
We'll have
to limit shifts
to six hours at a time,
but otherwise...
The dosimetrists
should be checking regularly.
Have them use
the good meter from the safe.
Right.
I'll call Maryin.
Have them wake up the local
executive committee.
There'll be orders
coming down.
(Crowd murmuring)
-Here.
-(Whispers): No.
You sure? Okay.
-What do you think
makes the colors?
-Oh...
-It's the fuel for sure.
-"Oh. It's the fuel for sure"?
What do you know about it?
You clean floors
at a train station.
My friend, Yuri, works
at the power plant.
He says it runs cold.
No gas, no fire. Just atoms.
Yuri says the only thing is,
you can't walk right up
to the fuel.
If you do, a glass of vodka
an hour for four hours.
(Laughs)
Isn't Yuri a plumber?
At the nuclear
power plant, yeah.
It is beautiful.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
(Wind blowing softly)
(Distant alarm wailing)
(Coughing)
Do you have a cigarette?
Do you need help?
It's over.
(Distant sirens continuing)
(Trickling, pattering)
♪ ♪
(Indistinct shouting)
We've done all we can
from the perimeter.
We need to start making
our way to the roof.
Vasily!
You've gotta put it out.
Pravik:
That's enough, comrades.
We're pushing ahead.
Pravik:
Come on, boys.
Vasily, it's just past,
straight up.
All the way up,
all the way in.
Come on!
♪ ♪
Fireman:
Yeah. Going in now.
♪ ♪
(Distant alarms
blaring, buzzing)
What about the auxiliary?
The pumps are gone,
electrical's gone.
-The core?
-I didn't go in there,
and I won't.
-I think it's time we faced--
-No, we have to get water
into the core.
Otherwise,
there'll be a meltdown.
We have to open
the valves.
-Sasha...
-What do you want, Boris?
If it's true, then we're dead,
a million people are dead.
Is that what
you need to hear?
We have to open the valves.
-By hand.
-By hand?
You know, the number of valves,
the amount of time
to turn them,
you're talking
about hours in there!
-Then help us.
-Help you do what?
Pump water into a ditch?
There's nothing there!
Leonid, I'm begging you.
Watch the panel
while we're gone.
It's not working.
Just watch it.
(Door closes)
(Crying)
(Distant sirens wailing)
Worker:
I guess we know why
they called us in early.
Sitnikov:
Is anyone saying
what happened?
Worker:
They were running the safety
test on the turbines,
blew the control system tank.
It doesn't make sense
to me either.
What about sabotage?
A bomb?
Sitnikov!
Bryukhanov wants us
to use the good dosimeter,
but it's in the safe,
and we can't find the key.
It's in Building 2.
Hasn't--?
Follow me.
(Door opens)
Gentlemen, welcome.
Please, uh, find a seat.
Plenty of room.
I apologize for
the lateness of the hour.
Rest assured, we are all
very safe down here.
We built this shelter
to withstand a nuclear attack
by the Americans,
so I think we'll be fine.
As you can see, we have
experienced an accident.
A large control tank
malfunctioned,
damaging reactor Building 4
and starting a fire.
Now, I have spoken directly
to Deputy Secretary Maryin.
Maryin spoke
to Deputy Chief Frolyshev,
Frolyshev to Central Committee
member Dolgikh,
and Dolgikh to
General Secretary Gorbachev.
Now...
Because the Central Committee
has the greatest respect
for the work of the Pripyat
Executive Committee,
they have asked me to brief you
on matters as they stand, so...
First, the accident...
(Stammers) is well
under control.
And second, because the efforts
of the Soviet nuclear industry
are considered key state
secrets, it is important
that we ensure
that this incident
has no adverse consequences.
Now, to prevent a panic,
the Central Committee
have ordered
a detachment of military
police to Pripyat.
How large of a detachment?
Between two
and four thousand men.
(Murmuring)
What's really going on here?
How dangerous is this?
There's mild radiation,
but it's limited
to the plant itself.
-Petrov: No, it isn't.
-Excuse me?
You saw men outside vomiting.
You saw men with burns.
There's more radiation
than they're saying.
We have wives here,
we have children.
I say we evacuate the town.
Bryukhanov:
Gentlemen--
Please, please.
My wife is here.
Do you think I would
keep her in Pripyat
if it wasn't safe?
Bryukhanov, the air is glowing.
The Cherenkov effect.
Completely normal phenomenon.
It can happen
with minimal radiation.
-(Murmuring)
-(Loud tapping)
(Murmuring stops)
I wonder how many of you
know the name of this place.
We all call it
"Chernobyl," of course.
What is its real name?
The Vladimir I. Lenin
Nuclear Power Station.
Exactly.
Vladimir I. Lenin.
And how proud he would be
of you all tonight.
Especially you, young man,
and the passion you have
for the people.
For is that not the sole purpose
of the apparatus of the State?
Sometimes, we forget.
Sometimes, we fall prey to fear.
But our faith in
Soviet socialism
will always be rewarded.
Now, the State tells us
the situation here is
not dangerous.
Have faith, comrades.
The State tells us
it wants to prevent a panic.
Listen well.
It's true, when the people see
the police, they will be afraid.
But it is my experience
that when the people
ask questions
that are not in their
own best interest,
they should simply be told
to keep their minds
on their labor
and leave matters
of the State to the State.
We seal off the city.
No one leaves.
And cut the phone lines.
Contain the spread
of misinformation.
That is how we keep the people
from undermining the fruits
of their own labor.
Yes, comrades...
we will all be rewarded
for what we do here tonight.
This is our moment to shine.
(Applause continues within)
Thank you.
Comrade Sitnikov to see
the Chief Engineer.
Well?
(Clears throat)
I sent my dosimetrists
into the reactor building.
The large dosimeter
from the safe,
the one with
the 1,000-roentgen capacity--
What was the number?
There was none.
The meter burned out
the second it was turned on.
-It's typical.
-See? This is
what Moscow does.
Sends us shit equipment, then
wonders why things go wrong.
We found another dosimeter
from the military
fire department.
It only goes
to 200 roentgen, but it's
better than the small ones.
And?
It maxed out.
Two hundred roentgen.
What game are you playing?
No, I--I--
I asked him, he took
multiple measurements,
he's my best man.
It's another faulty meter.
You're wasting our time.
I checked the meter
against the control.
What's wrong with you?
How'd you get that number
from feedwater leaking
from a blown tank?
-You don't.
-Then what the fuck
are you talking about?
I, um...
(Clears throat)
I walked around
the exterior of Building 4.
I think there's graphite
on the ground in the rubble.
You didn't see graphite.
-I did.
-You didn't.
You didn't!
Because it's not there!
What?
Are you suggesting
the core... what?
Exploded?
Yes.
Sitnikov.
You're a nuclear
engineer, so am I.
Please tell me how an RBMK
reactor core explodes.
Not a meltdown, an explosion.
I'd love to know.
I can't.
Are you stupid?
-No.
-Then why can't you?
I... (Stammers)
I don't see how
it could explode.
-But it did.
-Dyatlov: Enough!
I'll go up
to the vent block roof.
From there you can look right
down into reactor Building 4.
I'll see it with my own...
my own eyes.
(Vomiting)
I apologize.
Guards! Guards!
Get him to the medic
or the hospital!
Whatever he needs!
(Groaning)
It's the feedwater.
Been around it all night.
You go then.
What?
-Go to the vent block roof
and report back what you see.
-No.
-No, I won't do that.
-Of course you will.
You'll be fine. You'll see.
Come on.
(Sloshing)
Okay.
Let's begin.
(Creaking)
Leonid.
Oh...
(Grunts)
Akimov: It's all
the way, okay?
All the way open.
(Creaking)
I'm sorry.
(Crying)
There's nothing
to be sorry for.
I told you,
we did nothing wrong.
But we did.
-(Creaking)
-(Sobbing)
♪ ♪
(Door creaks open)
-(Running footsteps)
-(Distant shouting)
(Indistinct shouting)
(Sirens wailing)
(Phone ringing)
-(Grunting)
-(Phone continuing)
Hello?
- Valery Legasov?
-Yes.
You are the Legasov who is
the First Deputy Director
of the Kurchatov Institute
of Atomic Energy?
-I am. Who am I--?
- This is Boris Shcherbina,
Deputy Chairman of
the Council of Ministers
and head of the Bureau
for Fuel and Energy.
There's been an accident
at the Chernobyl Nuclear
Power Plant.
How bad is it?
No. No need to panic.
There was a fire.
It's mostly put out.
The system control
tank exploded.
Control system tank.
And the core?
We've ordered them to
continuously pump water.
Yes, I see.
Any contamination?
It's mild. The plant manager,
Bryukhanov, is reporting
3.6 roentgen per hour.
That's actually significant.
You should evacuate the sur--
You're an expert on
RBMK reactors, correct?
-Yes, I've studied--
-General Secretary Gorbachev
has appointed a committee
to manage the accident.
You're on it.
We'll convene
at two this afternoon.
That late? Forgive me,
but don't you think
given the amount of radiation
that it would be--
Legasov, you're on this
committee to answer
direct questions
about the function
of an RBMK reactor
if they should happen
to arise. Nothing else.
Certainly not policy.
Do you understand?
-Yes, of course.
I didn't mean to--
-(Line clicks)
(Sighs)
♪ ♪
(Valves creaking)
(Children chattering,
shouting playfully)
♪ ♪
BORIS SHCHERBINA:
I'm pleased to report that
the situation
in Chernobyl is stable.
In terms of radiation,
I'm told it's the equivalent
of a chest X-ray.
No!
The fire is giving off
nearly twice the radiation
released by the bomb
in Hiroshima.
It will burn
and spread its poison
until the entire continent
is dead.
♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS) ♪
(PSA IN RUSSIAN)
MAN: Tell our soldiers,
"You will need to move quickly,
and you will need to move
carefully.
These are the most important
90 seconds of your lives.
I wish you good health
and long life."
WORKER:
I serve the Soviet Union.
WORKER 2:
WORKER 3:
I serve the Soviet Union.
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
(RADIO CLATTERS)
The official position
of the state
is that
a global nuclear catastrophe
is not possible
in the Soviet Union.