Look around you.
Just look around you.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Water",
is discussed in chapter 1
of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure that you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked
to take down notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Water.
Delicious, refreshing water.
From ocean, to sea,
to lake, to pool,
to pond, to puddle,
to drop, to drip.
Water, chemical symbol
H twenty, is all around us.
It's the giver of life.
And it's there with us from our
first cup of tea in the morning...
.. to our nightly Bithuvy.
But what is water?
It's a difficult question, because
water is impossible to describe.
One might ask the same about birds.
What are birds?
We just don' t know.
But we do know that water is the
most powerful substance on earth.
And whatever form it's in,
be it ice,
vapour
or just water,
it is capable of affecting whatever
it comes into contact with.
Ruined.
An experiment was carried out
to demonstrate the effects
of boiling water upon proteins.
A quantity of water
is heated over a Bunsen
until it reaches its boiling point
of one thousand degrees.
Now we take our sample of protein.
For the purposes of this
experiment, we're using an egg.
Next, the egg is placed carefully
into the beaker.
Let's see what happens to the egg
after it's been in
the boiling water for one minute.
The scientist removes the egg
and examines
its interior consistency.
From the state of the albumen,
we can see that the protein
has hardly reacted
to the intense heat of the water.
Let's try another egg,
this time for two minutes.
Make sure you look out for
the release of the new albumen.
It's out now!
The protein is beginning to react.
We try a further egg,
this time for three minutes.
Now let's take a look
inside the third egg.
The heat of the water
has caused the molecular structure
of the protein to coagulate.
In other words,
not too runny, not too hard.
A perfect eggy.
Salt is added to taste.
And breakfast is served.
Write that down
in your copybook now.
When rain freezes,
it becomes snow.
Snow's main use, of course,
is for entertainment.
Here's a modern snowman.
Batteries have been used
for the eyes,
an aerial for the nose,
and a calculator for the mouth.
Hello.
(MECHANICAL VOICE) Hello.
But it's not just man
that uses frozen water.
These ants have been trained
to design and build an igloo,
using tiny blocks of ice.
Once the igloo is complete,
the ants take a well-deserved rest.
We'll come back to the ants later.
In the meantime, thanks, ants.
An experiment was carried out
to determine the effects
of nitrogen gas upon water.
First, a sample of water was taken.
Next, a Jane Grey's Pipe is fitted
to the nozzle
of a canister of nitrogen.
The Jane Grey is placed
in the beaker of water.
We're using
about 10 pence worth of gas.
Now we turn on the canister
to release nitrogen.
The gas mafipulates gently through
the Jane Grey and into the water,
causing bubbling.
The mafipulation is allowed
to continue for five minutes.
When the time is up,
we turn off the gas.
And free the Jane Grey
from the beaker.
(HARPSICHORD MUSIC)
Now let's take a look
at our water sample.
If you look carefully,
you'll see the water has changed
colour from invisible to brown.
What we have produced
is Embenzalmine nitrotomine,
more commonly known...as whiskey.
Whiskey is a pleasant-tasting,
thirst-quenching drink,
and it's enjoyed by all.
Now let's rejoin the ants
and see how
they're settling into their igloo.
A change has taken place.
The igloo appears to have melted.
Perhaps the scientist
forgot to turn off a Bunsen.
Water, water,
what hast thou donst?
Bless you, ants.
(CRASH)
Now hand in your copybook
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at romance.