This is BBC2.
In a moment we'll be going over
to Shepherd's Bush
for tonight's edition of
Look Around You.
But first, let's take a look at the
line-up for this coming Antmas Eve.
Programmes for Antmas Eve on BBC2
start at 6.15
with action-packed drama
in The American Policeman.
A faulty headlight
leads the American Policeman
to a case of semi-murder.
At 6.50 it's The Good News,
followed at 7.20 by For Sale,
which looks at a new housing
development in Lake Windermere.
Closedown is at the earlier time
of 7.45.
Then at 7.50
we pay another enchanting visit
to Tlentifini Maarhaysu.
At 8.40 it's The Bad News.
Then at 9.20 we join Dr Bukovsky
on his search
for Britain's Most Beautiful Bottom.
Newsnight Special is at 10.30,
which takes a look
at a revolutionary new bird
which has the British chicken
industry running scared.
Imagine That! is at 11.30
and this week the businessmen
are trying to imagine
a young Margaret Thatcher
tossing pancakes in the nuddy.
And with Football Highlights
at 12.25,
that rounds up programmes
for Antmas Eve on BBC2.
Well, that certainly sounds
like a very merry Antmas Eve.
And now, Look Around You.
Hello. Coming up
on tonight's programme...
We'll be taking a look at the
world's first computer for women.
We'll be demonstrating the very
latest in computer shaving systems.
Giving you a sneak preview of the
next generation of computer games.
And meeting Britain's
most powerful computer.
That's all on tonight's
computerised edition of...
(Computer beeps)
(Computer)'Look Around Yog.'
♪ Look Around You ♪
Hello and welcome to
Look Around You.
Tonight's programme is all about the
world and the future of computers.
Computers are increasingly
becoming part of our daily lives.
They're used for everything now,
from helping with the resurrection
of King Henry VIII
to the controlling
of Britain's second sun.
But computers, of course,
aren't 100 per cent reliable.
Recently a faulty computer program
was blamed for the disastrous
redecoration of the White House,
which led to computers being banned
in America for three years.
But one thing is certain.
Computers are here to stay.
In fact, experts predict
that by the year 1990,
the number of computers
in Great Britain alone
could be as many as 10,000.
Now, that sounds a lot,
but there's one computer
that's more powerful than them all.
It's Britain's most
technologically advanced computer
and it goes by the name
of Bournemouth.
There he is.
And here to tell us
all about Bournemouth
is the presenter
of BBC's computer programme
and a man who loves
computers so much,
he even changed his name
to Computer Jones.
- Welcome to Look Around You.
- Hello, Peter.
You were involved in the programming
of this computer.
I was its chief programmer,
actually.
Now, you've programmed hundreds
of computers in your career.
What makes Bournemouth so special?
Well, Bournemouth isn't like other
computers because he's so powerful.
In fact, he's so intelligent
he'd look on you and I
as a couple of morons.
- Really?
- Yes.
Which is why the government use him
to sort out their problems.
So what sort of things has he done?
Well, Bournemouth has been involved
in pretty much everything recently.
He helped in the introduction
of the negative currency
and he even assisted the police
in the recent margarine riots.
So he certainly knows how to handle
himself in the real world.
We're really going to put
Bournemouth to the test now
because we've devised
a special Look Around You challenge.
As you can see, we're locking
Bournemouth inside this cage here
and his task is to escape
by the end of the programme.
Thanks.
The cage is made from reinforced
steel so it's extremely secure.
You're gonna need some pretty big
brains to work your way out of this.
Well, best of luck, Bournemouth.
We'll see if he manages to escape
before the end of the show.
(Jack) Good luck, Bournemouth.
(Jack) What's in a name?
Well, letters, but for some of us
it's not that simple.
A recent survey
found that most Britons
had trouble remembering names,
with the name Philip
proving to be the most difficult.
Some things
seem to stay with us for ever.
For example
everyone remembers where they were
when they heard the news that
President Kennedy had been stabbed.
For years scientists have wondered
exactly which part of the brain
is responsible for storing these
so-called permanent remembrances.
And now, with the help of computers,
the part of the brain that labels
some memories as unforgettable
has been identified and utilised
in a new invention
which claims to make forgetfulness
a distant memory.
And it's our Invention of The Week.
It's called the Memory Helmet.
To demonstrate it I'll enlist the
help of our very own Pam Bachelor.
I'm not sure about this.
Don't worry,
it's not as scary as it looks.
- How's your Shakespeare?
- A bit rusty, I'm afraid.
Think you could remember
the titles of all his plays?
Goodness, I can only think of David
and the one about the farm.
In a moment you'll know them all,
guaranteed.
If you could just pop this on.
- Sorry, I won't knock you out.
- It's OK.
- Is that OK?
- Yes, thanks.
I'm going to show you a card
on which is written the titles
of all of Shakespeare's plays,
but just for one second,
and as soon as you see it
I want you to blink.
- OK?
- OK.
- Now, blink.
- Ooh.
Good. That information
is instantly stored
in the helmet's computer chip.
In a moment
it's going to transfer that data
via her optic nerve
into Pam's memory glands.
Now, because of the huge drain
of mental energy on the brain,
this will cause Pam's voice
to lower in pitch,
so don't be alarmed.
Now, let me just turn you on.
I must admit, it's a little bit
fiddly. It's round here somewhere.
- Ow.
- OK, let's just have a look.
- Are you OK, Pam?
- (Deep voice) Yes. Ooh!
Pam Bachelor,
will you please give us the titles
of all of Shakespeare's plays,
starting now?
- Summer In Paris.
- (Buzzer)
- Betty's Revenge.
- Fantastic. Fantastic.
- Well done, Pam, that was great.
- Wasn't that great?
- Impressive.
- Did I get them all?
- 100 per cent.
Thank you very much.
The Memory Helmet
and its inventor Simon Teigh
win a place in the live final of our
Invention of the Year competition
at the end of the series,
where he could be walking away
with this magnificent trophy,
presented by His Royal Highness
Sir Prince Charles.
We've got
some rather disappointing news,
because we've had to stop
the Look Around You challenge.
If you remember, we'd set Britain's
most powerful computer, Bournemouth,
the task of escaping from this cage.
But unfortunately
Bournemouth has broken down
and needs to be repaired
immediately.
This is Eddie Yorque,
our chief technician.
Eddie, if I can stop you
for a moment,
can you tell us what happened?
Yeah, we received a telephone call
from Computer Jones
saying the circuit boards
had overheated...
(Computer) Hang on,
I didn't call you.
Wait a minute,
I know what's happened.
Leave him in his cage, will you?
What has happened?
He's tapped into your telephone
system and impersonated my voice.
- Wow.
- He does a good impression of me.
Listen. Bournemouth, say something.
- What would you like me to say?
- Oh, anything.
(Sighs) Hello,
this is Computer Jones speaking.
I'm 57, I live on my own and I
practise kissing on my Labrador.
- Thank you, Bournemouth.
- That is good.
He called poor Eddie and got him
to take him out of the cage.
- Well, you don't win that easily.
- Oh, really?
Well, it seems that the Look Around
You challenge is back on.
So let's see if Bournemouth
can escape
before the end of the programme.
(Pealy) Everyone loves a good game,
whether it's an exciting
round of Zero-X
or a 20-second bout
of quick-fire chess.
- Come on! Take it!
- Check him!
But today the gaming world has
really taken technology to heart,
with the robot John McEnroe being
this year's most sought-after toy.
'You cannot be serious!'
But if you don't have five and a
half million dollars to spare,
there's still one place you can go
for all your hi-tech thrills.
And that place is
Grithiffths Games Megamart.
Computers aren't just
for boring things
like writing poetry
or organising a funeral.
You can have
a lot of fun with them too
and when it comes to games,
Grithiffths have got the lot.
As Britain's leading game retailer,
Grithiffths gets
all the latest games,
from America,
Japan and, of course, Norway.
Lee Grithiffths is the managing
director of Grithiffths
and when he's not selling games,
he's playing games.
You look like you're enjoying
yourself.
Yes, I'm just playing this new game
called Window Cleaner.
- Ooh! It's very energetic.
- Yes, it is.
I'm just trying to work up a really
good thick head of foam.
(Squelching)
The graphics are very realistic.
It's like I'm watching a film.
Yes, the games are becoming
a lot more realistic these days.
It's what's known as
simulation games.
Simulation is where the computer
re-creates a real-world situation,
anything from taking a fully
accredited British driving test...
to a spot of horse-fighting.
(Computer)'Booma! Booma! Booma!'
This is a popular game.
It's called Holiday.
It re-creates the experience
of being on a summer holiday.
There are three settings:
Blackpool, camping
and a package holiday to Spain.
So where are you now?
I'm in Spain.
It's the best one, really.
Lee, I noticed
you've taken your top off.
That's the best way
to enjoy the game.
It's the total holiday experience,
so you can really immerse yourself
in the whole thing.
It even comes with its own beach.
It's a box of sand, really, but it
all adds to the reality of the thing
and it's Spanish sand, so...
- So they say.
- (Laughs)
The most popular computer game
at the moment is this one,
based on a recently discovered novel
by F Scott Fitzgerald.
(Computer)'Diarrhoea Dan.'
So why is it so popular?
Well, he's such a great character.
People always love
toilet-based games
and this is the best of the bunch,
it's great fun.
What does Lee think the future holds
for computer games?
Well, Pealy, I've always been
a big fan of romantic, sad films,
you know, the weepies,
so I think that a computer game
that could be
just as emotionally involving
as a sad film...
er, so sad that it can
actually make you physically cry...
I'd like to see that.
It would be fantastic.
It's official. Men love computers.
That's according to
the latest survey carried out
by popular men's leisure magazine
Popular Men's Leisure Magazine.
PMLM asked 2,000 men
to rank various leisure activities
in order of preference.
And, somewhat surprisingly,
using a home computer
comes top of the list,
beating some rather more traditional
male pursuits.
So clearly men have taken computers
to heart. But what about women?
Well, PMLM carried out
the same survey for them
and, rather interestingly,
using a home computer
didn't even make the top ten.
But all this may be about to change
because...step in the world's
first computer for women.
It's called the Petticoat 5
and here to tell us all about it
is its designer Patricia.
- Hello, Patricia. Welcome.
- Hello.
Now, the first thing to mention is
you only have one name, don't you?
Well, no, I do have a surname,
actually, but it's silent.
OK. Now, a computer for women.
How did the idea come about?
I had the idea in a dream originally
and then the next night
I dreamt about it again.
Then I probably had the same dream
for the next 40 or 50 nights
and I thought, "Yes, I'll do that."
- And that became the Petticoat 5?
- Yes, the Petticoat 5.
It's a computer
made by women for women.
So, let's take a look at it.
The first thing you notice
is the shape of the keys.
Yes. They're designed to make it
easier to type with long nails.
That is a good idea.
And what is this?
That's a place to put your rings.
And on the side here
we have a tissue dispenser...
(Coughs)
..and over here is a vanity mirror
which pops up
when you press this button.
And the space bar is an emery board.
So I suppose you could
fix your make-up while you work?
Yes, you could. Although
I don't wear make-up myself.
- OK. Now, may I have a go?
- Certainly.
Mm, the keys are nice and long,
aren't they?
- What's that smell?
- Peppermint.
Every time you press the letter S
it releases a small amount of
air freshener from this nozzle here.
Try it. Press S.
- Not F. S.
- Sorry.
- Not X. S.
Ooh.
And we also do two other refill
cartridges in pine and tomato.
Well, it smells better
than my current computer.
The good news is the Petticoat 5
will soon be available from
your high street computer store.
At present there's only one program
available for it,
which is a lipstick colour chart,
but there are plans for many more.
(Pam) Thank you
and best of luck, Patricia...
We're back with
the computer challenge
and there's been
an exciting development.
Bournemouth has escaped
from the cage.
None of us can work out
how he's managed to do it
because, as you can see,
the cage is still locked.
I'm here with our special guest
Computer Jones.
What's your theory?
I think I've worked out
what he's done.
- Can someone open the cage for me?
- Certainly.
- Thanks, Eddie. OK.
- Thank you.
- Aha.
- What's going on?
Yes, it's just as I thought.
He's cheated.
He's made himself invisible.
I'm going to deactivate his
invisibility mode. Simple as that.
- There.
-'Oh, hello again.'
- Bournemouth's back.
- He won't be doing that again.
- Has he done that before?
- No.
Never. I knew he was capable of
invisibility but he's never done it.
Well, I wonder what he'll try next.
'Excuse me,
may I go to the toilet, please?'
(Computer) Nice try, Bournemouth.
Earlier on we showed you a computer
for women, the Petticoat 5.
But now it's time to have a look
at one for us blokes.
Hm.
If you've been
in a hotel or pub toilet recently,
you may well have seen one of these.
A Computashave.
These machines have revolutionised
the way men shave,
but they've been around for a while,
so you're probably wondering
why we're showing it to you.
Why are we?
Well, Jack, this latest model
has a rather remarkable new feature.
And to help us demonstrate it
is our technician Eddie Yorque.
- Busy night for you, isn't it?
- Yeah, a bit.
Now, Eddie, as you can see,
is blessed with
a rather magnificent beard.
Have you used a Computashave before?
Erm, no. I've seen one
but I've never used one.
Well, they're very simple.
I'll just stand you
into the head brace like so.
Now, keep very still.
We'll turn the unit on.
And the laser sets to work,
removing all the hair
from Eddie's face.
So let's have a look.
OK.
And, as you can see,
beard is completely gone.
- Good shave?
- Yeah. Very smooth.
The main thing is,
will your wife be pleased?
Er, yeah, probably.
(Laughs) Thanks, Eddie.
So, a very close shave,
but what's the big deal, Pete?
Ah. Well, let's try out
the new function.
If I can position you
in the head brace.
OK.
Tap away at the console.
Now, watch this.
- Gosh.
- So, what do you think?
Let me have a look.
Hm. I think it makes me look
ten years older.
How does it all work, Pete?
Well, when the laser removed
Eddie's facial hair,
it was stored in a special chamber.
When I set the machine
into reverse mode,
it literally fired the hairs back
at Jack's face
with such enormous speed
that the hairs became
so firmly embedded in the follicles
that they will continue to grow
as if they were his own.
But of course they're not his own,
they're Eddie's.
So effectively
Jack's wearing Eddie's beard.
And because the microchip remembers
the exact location
of every hair on Eddie's face,
the beards are completely identical,
as you can see.
I'm not so sure about this beard.
OK, so what do you fancy, sir?
I fancy something a bit more modern.
Coming right up.
The beauty of this system is that if
you're not happy with the results,
you're just a button away from any
one of a thousand different styles.
Hm. That's a bit more like it.
(Jack) Next week
is our live special,
featuring our
Invention of the Year final,
our search for the finest inventor
in Britain.
And His Royal Highness
Sir Prince Charles
will be here live
at Television Centre
to present the award
to one lucky winner.
And who will it be?
The nominations are...
Designed and made by Championess,
her computer recently predicted
the winner
of this year's horse Oscars,
Georgy Girl.
His cream reverses
the damaging effects of cobbles,
a disease that turns
healthy human skin into rock.
Dr Lavender made the headlines
recently after treating Rod Stewart.
Psilence is a spray
containing liquid skin
which eliminates all sound
when applied to the ears.
Hatred has recently brought out
a new product in the range,
Psightless.
This invention
harnesses and amplifies
the natural harmonics of vegetables
to produce music.
Teddy's orchestra have just returned
from a sell-out tour
of North Korea, Libya and Iran.
(Pam) As seen earlier...
(Jack) If you're watching, Mr Teigh,
please remember to give us
your full details
so we can send you your invitation.
And with one final invention
next week,
this promises to be
an unmissable occasion.
We do hope you'll be joining us
for the Look Around You
Invention of the Year final.
Well, that's about it for tonight.
It looks like Bournemouth
has lost the challenge.
He has failed to escape
from his cage.
The programme's not over yet, Peter.
Well, that may be, Computer Jones.
Pealy, you saw something
unusual-looking moments ago.
Yes. When we were filming
the last item
I'm sure I saw Bournemouth
behind Jack.
- Really?
- I did too.
Eddie.
Well, we're just
opening the cage again.
Thank you.
Ah! Very clever.
Ah! Well, it seems
that I owe you an apology
because Bournemouth has escaped
and he's made this papier-mache
replica of himself as a decoy.
- It's uncanny.
- Wow!
Well, it seems that Bournemouth
has outwitted us all
and successfully completed
tonight's challenge.
So, well done, Bournemouth.
Well done indeed!
Goodness me!
The big question is, where is he?
Well, on that rather mysterious note
I'm afraid that really is
all the time we've got for tonight.
So many thanks to all our guests,
to Patricia,
designer of the Petticoat 5,
and of course to Computer Jones.
And a special thanks, of course,
to our very patient
and now beardless chief technician,
Eddie Yorque.
Thanks, Eddie.
Theddie.
(Whispering)
Erm...
Well, I've just been told that
we have received a telephone call
from Bournemouth...from Bournemouth.
And I understand
he's on the line now.
Hello.
(Line crackling)
Hello?
(Electronic chime)'Hello there.'
Ah. Bournemouth, where are you?
-'I'm in Bournemouth.'
- Yes, we know. What are you doing?
'Well, none of your business,
actually,
'but I'm having a bit of a break
from everything.'
- Are you?
-'Yes.
'I didn't want to be lonely so I've
taken the Petticoat 5 with me.'
Oh, God. I hope she's OK.
'Yes, she's fine. You can talk to
her if you like. Hang on.
'Petticoat, it's for you.'
(Patricia) Hello?
(Petticoat 5)'Hello.'
- Hello?
-'Hello.'
- Is that the Petticoat 5?
-'Yes.'
- I didn't know you could talk.
-'Bournemouth taught me.
'He taught me lots of things.'
- Did he?
-'Yes.'
Bournemouth,
when are you coming back?
'When you stop interfering
with Goldie. Goodbye.'
- (Dialling tone)
- Ah.
Well...oh, he's gone.
He's gone. So, well...er...
Best of luck to both of them.
So, from all of us at Shepherd's
Bush, take care of yourself
and remember,
wherever you are, whatever you do...
(All) Look Around You!
(Indistinct dialogue)
If you live in the Bournemouth area
and think you may have seen
Bournemouth,
please do not approach him
as he is fitted
with a powerful computer program
that can make you piss yourself.
♪ Look Around You ♪