You're watching BBC2.
And now it's time
to go over to Shepherd's Bush
for a very special live edition
of Look Around You.
Hello and welcome
from outside BBC Television Centre
to a special live edition
of Look Around You.
Thanks, Jack. Yes, we've got a very
exciting show for you tonight.
Well, they seem excited,
because tonight is the grand final
of the Look Around You
Invention of the Year competition.
And arriving here very shortly
to present tonight's award
is His Royal Highness,
Sir Prince Charles.
- So stay tuned.
- Cue the titles.
♪ Look Around You ♪
Hello and welcome to Studio 1
for this, the live final
of the Look Around You
Invention of the Year competition.
Tonight's show is the culmination
of a massive, nationwide search
to find the cream
of British inventiveness.
If you've been following the series,
you will have met
tonight's finalists,
five British inventors,
each hoping to walk away
with this magnificent trophy,
presented later on, in the studio,
by HRH Sir Prince Charles.
And all the finalists
are with us here tonight.
And they are...
Dr Phillip Lavender
and the Anti-Cobbling Cream.
Leonard Hatred, and the personal
soundproofing spray,
Psilence.
Teddy Clarke,
and the Vegetable Orchestra System.
Paul Alan and Championess, with
the horse race predicting computer.
And Simon Teigh,
with the Memory Helmet.
And may we have a big
round of applause for all of them.
(Applause)
And we'll be meeting them all once
again later on in the programme.
Now it's time to meet the inventors
of our sixth and final entry,
Pat Taylor and Sam MacNamara.
(Applause)
- Hello. Welcome to Look Around You.
- Thank you.
Your invention is unique, isn't it?
- Yes.
- Tell us what it is.
- Er, it's...
- A sex-change machine.
- Sex-change machine?
- Yes.
Well, here it is.
Let's have a little look at it.
I have to say, it does look a little
like a dry-cleaning machine.
(Laughter)
That's because it uses
a lot of the same technology
as a dry-cleaning machine,
except rather than using detergent,
what it does is it actually
bombards you with hormones.
I see. Now, I understand
your machine can change your sex
within about five minutes,
is that correct?
Yes, and the beauty of the system
is that it's completely reversible.
If you're not happy
being a man or a woman,
- you can change back straightaway.
- Really?
Yes. In fact,
I myself have changed sex 22 times.
- (Applause)
- And Sam,
how many times have you had sex?
(Laughter)
Sorry. Erm...how many times
have you changed sex?
Erm...
Probably about 50 times.
- About 60 times.
- (Applause)
Gosh! Now we have a first
for British television tonight,
because Sam is going to change
into a woman live on the programme.
We'll see Sam's transformation
a little later on.
Thank you both. Sam, if you'd
like to get into the machine?
(Applause)
(Machine humming)
Peter.
Thanks, Pam.
I'm looking forward to that.
I believe that outside the studio,
Jack's been joined by
a special guest.
No, it's not Sir Prince Charles, but
it's somebody you'll all recognise.
That's right. I'm here with
an old friend of Look Around You,
the presenter of BBC2's computer
programme, Computer Jones.
- Hello.
- Hello, Jack.
Computer Jones, who do you think
is going to win tonight?
As a computer man, I'd have to say
the horse-racing computer,
but I'm interested to see
the sex machine in operation.
And you have an update for us since
you were last on the show.
Yes. If you remember,
I was on your programme
and I met a very special
and beautiful lady called Patricia.
That's Patricia, the designer of the
computer for women, the Petticoat 5.
Yes, that's right. And when we met,
Jack, it was truly wonderful.
We went out to dinner after the
programme and had a wonderful time.
We talked for hours and hours
and we ended up sleeping together.
Well, the very next day,
we got married.
That's wonderful!
Congratulations from all of us.
Yes, congratulations.
And I've just been told
that Sir Prince Charles
has just driven past
the Royal Skeleton Society,
so he shouldn't be too long now.
(Cheering)
Back to you in the studio!
Thanks, Pealy. Well, while we wait
for Sam to complete his sex change,
let's go and meet some of our other
contestants tonight.
The devastating disease
geodermic grenatitis,
more commonly known as "Cobbles",
has the terrible effect of turning
the sufferer into a pile of rocks.
It's the focus
of our next invention,
the Anti-Cobbling Cream,
created by Dr Phillip Lavender.
- Hello, Doctor.
- Hello, Pam.
It's nice too see you.
You're looking very well.
Thank you very much. I suppose
I may have lost a couple of stones.
(Laughter)
Now, Doctor, your cream is designed
to reverse the effects of Cobbles,
turning the rocky surface
back into healthy skin.
That's right, Pam.
When we last saw you, your cream
only lasted for 15 minutes.
But you've made a breakthrough,
haven't you?
Yes, we've now formulated
a stronger version of the cream,
which means that it leads to
a complete and permanent recovery.
- That is wonderful.
- (Applause)
Thank you very much.
Now Doctor, I have to ask you...
Why have you chosen
not to take your own cure?
Well, that's a good question, Pam.
I suppose the answer is that
I'm rather used to the way I am now.
People are always very kind to me.
I receive a lot of attention and
sympathy.
And, of course, I can still fly.
Goodbye.
Psilence is a spray
containing liquid skin
that is applied directly to the ear
to reduce sound.
- (Man) Eliminate sound.
- I'm sorry, eliminate sound.
And I'm here with its inventor,
Leonard Hatred.
(Applause)
Now, although you live
in the countryside,
you are plagued by noise.
Yes, the abattoir is still
directly opposite the house.
And my burglar alarm's
started to play up
and it goes off
every ten to twelve minutes,
which means I have to go
down to the cellar to turn it off,
go all the way,
which is not only annoying,
but it's physically demanding.
On top of that, I understand that
your next-door neighbour's son...
- Simon...
- ..has formed a punk rock band.
- UK Vomit.
- Charming. Well...
For those of you who haven't seen
Leonard's aerosol, erm...
he's going to give us
a quick demonstration now.
So Leonard's going to spray it
directly onto this model...
- Oh, dear.
- (Man) Allow me.
I'll get it.
We're having a slight...
nozzle problem.
Have you got it?
The lost nozzle.
Can we get somebody
to give us a hand here?
- Got it?
- (Applause)
Well done.
OK.
As you can see,
the ear is completely sealed up.
We got there in the end.
Thank you very much, Leonard Hatred.
- I have to do the other ear.
- I'm sorry, we don't have time.
And we can now rejoin Sam MacNamara,
who I believe has completed
his sex-change operation.
You have plenty of time
for the sex-change folks.
- Would you please be quiet?
- It's a fix.
Pam, I believe you're with
Sam McNamara now.
Thank you. The sex-change machine
has come to the end of its cycle,
so let's take a look at Sam.
(Leonard) Fix! It's all a fix!
- (Pam) Wow!
- (Applause)
That is amazing.
What a transformation.
- (High voice) Thank you.
- So how do you feel?
I feel fine. Just more feminine.
Don't she look lovely? Come on.
(Applause)
(Wolf whistle)
You've got a better bust than me.
Well, best of luck, both of you,
for later on.
Now let's go back to Jack and Pealy
to find out the latest
on Sir Prince Charles.
Thanks, Pam. Well, he's only a
few minutes away now.
He's just past Goldstein Cathedral
and the crowd
are still very excited.
(Cheering and applause)
I could do with
a can of that Psilence spray myself!
Well, we've got an amazing crowd
here, as I just said.
And there's one very special person
with us tonight.
His name is Adam Sandwich.
Hello, Adam. Who are you exactly?
I'm the British
Counting Backwards champion.
Oh, that's fantastic!
I'm sure the crowd would love
to hear a bit of backwards counting.
- Would you do a bit for us?
- All right.
I'll count backwards
from 20 down to 10.
Great. So let's have a handclap
to get the rhythm going.
20...19...18...17...16...
15...13...14...13...
12...11...10...
Fantastic!
Thank you, Adam. Pealy.
Thanks, Jack. Wasn't that great?
I wish I could do that.
Joining us now is someone
you will recognise from the series,
because he is Britain's
foremost keyboard expert.
It's Synthesizer Patel.
- Hello, Synthesizer Patel.
- Hi, Pealy.
Who would you like to see win
tonight?
Well, the sex-change machine
is really something.
If I had invented that, they would
have to call me Sex-Change Patel.
We last saw you demonstrating
some of your incredible synthesizers
on our programme about music.
Yes, that was a lot of fun,
but good things,
they say, cannot last forever,
because very soon
after the programme,
someone stole all my synthesizers.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
That must have been awful.
They also took some of my clothes,
my sister's watch,
my science calculator, some shoes,
my spare glasses
and a wallet containing L50,
which I had left on top
of one of the synthesizers.
Well, sorry and thank you very much
for joining us, Synthesizer Patel.
And once again, so sad to hear
your sorry news there.
I think we're almost ready to go
back to the studio, where Peter...
They didn't take this one, hey,
Pealy? Come on!
(♪ Funky synthesizer solo)
Synthesizer Patel there,
completely taking over the show.
And now let's meet
our final two contestants tonight.
The Vegetable Orchestra System
harnesses the natural
harmonic vibrations of vegetables,
which allows them
to accurately mimic
a variety of musical instruments.
Its inventor is Teddy Clarke.
Hello, Teddy. Nice to see you again.
It's nice to be here, Pam.
Now, what have you and the orchestra
been up to since we last saw you?
Well, we've had
a very fruitful time,
if you'll pardon the pun.
We've given a lot of concerts
up and down the country.
We've even performed for the Pope,
down the phone line,
which was a great honour.
And I understand you've also
recorded some music for a film.
Yes. We're featured on the
soundtrack to the current Bond film.
And you also have a newcomer
to the Vegetable Orchestra.
That's right.
This piece of toast here.
We're very fortunate
to have her on loan
from the Bristol Breakfast
Orchestra.
Right. Now, you're going to play
a few bars from the new Bond theme.
We are. Thank you, Pam.
(♪ Orchestral rendition
of Bond theme)
♪ James Bond ♪
- (Applause)
- Thank you. Teddy Clarke.
Peter.
Our next contestant is our
only four-legged inventor tonight.
Championess is
a particularly clever horse
who have devised
and constructed a computer
which can accurately predict
the winners of horse races.
She's here with her owner,
Paul Alan.
(Applause)
Hello, Paul.
And congratulations to you both
on getting through to the final.
Now, Championess' computer has
made her a wealthy horse, hasn't it?
- That's right, yes.
- How much money has she made?
Her total winnings are currently
in the region of 20 million guineas.
- 20 million!
- (Applause)
What has she spent her money on?
Well, she's bought herself
a hotel for horses.
(Audience giggles)
She's become very interested in art
and collecting paintings.
She's very fond of Andy Warhol.
- And she loves ceramics.
- And she's interested in politics?
Yes, she's made large donations
to both the Conservative
and Labour parties.
Really? Well, thank you very much
and best of luck.
(Applause)
Now, our final invention tonight
is the Memory Helmet,
created by Simon Teigh.
Mr Teigh was meant to be here
tonight
but he forgot to come. Jack.
(Leonard) Should have worn his
Memory Helmet then, shouldn't he?
(No sound)
Hear me now? Can you hear me?
Oh, good.
We lost sound there for a moment
but we're back on.
Sir Prince Charles
will be here any moment now
but before he arrives, we've had
a few phone calls about this banner.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
Can you enlighten us?
What does "Hot Jon" mean?
Well, Hot Jon. I'm glad you
noticed. It's...
(No sound)
That's Hot Jon.
It's been driving me mad as well,
but now we know.
I'm gonna have to stop you there
because Sir Prince Charles
is just pulling into the BBC.
(Cheering and applause)
(Pealy) Yes, and here comes
the Prince!
It's a wonderful fanfare
for Sir Prince Charles.
- It's an electric atmosphere here.
All wanting to know
who's going to win.
The Prince seems to have noticed
our contestant, Dr Phillip Lavender,
who's been flying around
Shepherd's Bush this evening.
Apologies if you're staring at
the back of the Prince's head.
He should be with us in a moment,
so back to the studio.
Sir Prince Charles will be here
in a moment to present the award.
So perhaps it's worth
taking this time
to have a look at
the magnificent trophy.
Here it is, and I'm going to let you
in to a little secret now.
This award was actually designed and
made by our very own Pam Bachelor.
Pam, this truly is
a beautiful object.
- Thank you.
- Tell us a bit about the design.
Well, the central part of it
is an egg,
which for me represents new life,
new beginnings, new inventions.
And it tapers to a point,
signifying the future.
And what's it made of?
Well, it's solid gold,
plated in tin.
So how long have you been interested
in metalwork?
I got into it
because an old boyfriend...
(Leonard) Load of rubbish.
Piece of junk.
Will you please be quiet?
- A baby could make that.
- (Teddy) Settle down.
- Shut up.
- I beg your pardon?
You are a very rude young man
and you're ruining it for everybody.
Oh, fuck off!
Ooh... Erm...
We apologise
for the strong language there
and hope it hasn't caused offence.
Well, we appear to be experiencing
a few problems
with our live broadcast
from Studio 1.
But I believe
we can now rejoin Look Around You.
Well, hello again. We're back with
the Invention of the Year final.
We apologise for the behaviour
of our finalist, Leonard Hatred.
He has now been disqualified
and removed from the studio
by our security guards,
who, I must say, have handled
the situation impeccably.
(Applause)
And now we're honoured to have His
Royal Highness Sir Prince Charles
with us in the studio
to present tonight's award.
So, Your Royal Highness,
can we hear from you now
who the winner is?
(Applause)
Ladies and gentlemen, first of all,
I want to say how grateful I am
to the BBC
and to the Look Around You team
in particular
for establishing this award.
When we set up this scheme,
I was delighted to work
hand in hand with Look Around You
to ensure that a large
number of people in this country
actually discover,
through the medium of television,
that there are some highly original,
potentially successful
and British ideas about.
I know the judges
found it extremely difficult
to decide the winner from such
a diverse range of products.
But in the end they agreed that the
winner of this year's award is...
(Drum roll)
The sex-change machine,
entered by Pat Taylor
and Sam MacNamara.
Marvellous. Well done.
Were you surprised?
We were indeed surprised, yes.
I don't know
where you're going to put it
but I hope you find
a suitable place.
And which one of you is which?
I'm Pat and this is Sam.
Sam was a woman earlier in the show.
He's now changed into a man.
- I mean, the other way around.
- Really?
Yes, sir.
You have had great success, haven't
you, with the production of it?
Yes. Dry-cleaners are always
getting rid of their old machines
and they're pretty easy to convert
into sex-change devices.
I hope it goes from
strength to strength. Mazel tov.
Thank you very much indeed.
Well, thank you,
Your Royal Highness.
- And congratulations...
- (Commotion)
(Shouting and screaming)
We're still experiencing problems
with our live broadcast,
but we hope to return to Studio 1
shortly.
In the meantime,
here's a short film.
One of the benefits of living
in the countryside
is the large variety of birds
you can see in the wild.
Here's a couple of finches.
Some finches can live
up to 60 years,
although these two
are probably only about 40.
Here's a robin.
I wonder what it's thinking about.
Here's a blackbird.
There's a thrush.
It's stuffed.
Here's a couple of hand birds.
One of them has caught a worm.
Now let's take a look
at a typical bird's nest.
This one belongs to a crow.
He's out at the moment,
so we can have a good look around.
The crow's made a sort of burglar
alarm out of old milk bottle tops.
Luckily, we've managed
to deactivate it.
In crow terms,
this one's probably a millionaire...
And we can now return
to Look Around You.
Well, welcome back. Um...
We've had some rather shocking
things happen here in Studio 1,
but thankfully,
the situation is now under control.
A few moments ago,
Leonard Hatred re-entered the studio
and caused havoc.
He forced Jack into
the sex-change machine,
and worse still, attacked Sir Prince
Charles with his can of Psilence.
But don't worry, the Prince is fine,
and has kindly and graciously agreed
to remain with us in the studio
until the end of the programme.
Thank you, Your Royal Highness.
- (Man) Well done, Charlie!
- (Applause)
We're still trying to free Jack
from the sex-change machine
but the good news is that
Leonard Hatred has been restrained.
So thank you to Dr Phillip Lavender
and to our excellent security men,
Hank Sullivan and Hank Fletcher.
Thanks, Hanks.
Thanks.
And thanks once again
to our winners,
and to almost all of our finalists,
for taking part in the competition.
Sadly, that's the last
in the present series.
But we wouldn't have been able
to do it without you, the viewers.
Thank you for staying with us
over the last six weeks,
and for all your phone calls
and letters.
It really means a lot to us.
Got it.
(Applause)
Are you OK?
(Applause and whistles)
(High voice) We'll see you again
in our next series,
when we'll be bringing you
more exciting developments
from the world and the future
of science and technology.
- Well done, Jack.
- I'm Jackie.
So, in the meantime,
from all of us here at Studio 1,
take care of yourself and remember,
wherever you are, whatever you do...
(All) Look Around You!
♪ Look Around You ♪