Look around you.
Just look around you.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Iron",
is discussed
in chapter 3 of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure that you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked to
take notes down from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Iron, or to give it its full name,
Iron De Havilland,
is one of the sturdiest
and heaviest of all elements.
(CRASH)
This is thanks largely
to its rigid molecular structure.
Here is a model
of an iron molecule.
And here is a model of a model
of an iron molecule,
modelled in iron.
Man has been using iron
since the Stone Age,
and over the years, we've garnered
a healthy respect for the metal,
so that Sundays are now devoted
to the cleaning and polishing
of all our iron possessions.
But it's not all work.
As a young child, you may have
played with iron filings,
counting and recounting them
over and over again,
and keeping a daily record
of the figures in your iron diary.
Some of you may even have tried
bending an iron spoon
using nothing
but the powers of your imagination.
It rarely works, but it's fun,
and that's what counts.
Of course, it's hard to know
what De Havilland himself,
the father of iron chemistry,
would make of all this,
but no doubt he'd probably
have a twinkle in his eye.
An experiment was carried out
to demonstrate the effects
of sulphuric acid upon iron.
First, a sample of iron
is placed upon a Ravenscroft pan.
(CRASH)
Next, a small quantity of sulphuric
acid is collected, via a pipette.
The bell is sounded
and the experiment can begin.
The scientist releases
a tiny drop of acid onto the iron,
probably only about point
point five point 05 microgallons.
Observe the reaction and note down
the results in your copybook.
The sulphuric acid has broken
the iron into its most basic form,
brown iron, or Bumcivilian.
Now watch what happens when the
scientist rings the bell this time.
(SILENCE)
The bell's not broken,
it's in good working order.
It's just that
when Bumcivilian is produced,
it has the effect of sucking in
all the sound from its vicinity.
Even with the scientist joining in,
we still hear nothing.
But after a few seconds,
the effect diminishes.
(SCIENTIST SHOUTS, BELL RINGS)
Let's take a look
at some of the ways iron is used.
Iron is used to make irons,
as well as thimbles and knives.
An iron horseshoe
is a popular item,
as it brings its owner good luck.
You've probably seen one
in your parents' car.
Amongst the most regular users
of iron in a professional capacity
are the police force, because
iron is used to make handcuffs.
And also this,
the face shackle,
worn by petty criminals.
The face shackle
is a kind of portable prison,
which must be worn around the clock
for periods of up to 18 months,
or three years
if you're a repeat offender.
The cheapest kind of iron
in modern usage is pig iron,
so called
because it's manufactured by pigs.
(CRASH)
Pigs are much more cost-effective
than humans,
and they work far longer hours
than any man would tolerate.
There are currently plans for them
to have their own trade union,
although whether this would work
in reality, nobody knows.
An experiment was carried out
to illustrate the effects
of electricity upon iron.
First, an iron pyramid
is placed upon the work surface.
Next, the pyramid is connected
to an electrical circuit,
powered by a 9-volt battery.
We're going to feed
both an AC and a DC current
through the ferric pyramid,
and so the battery itself
is connected to the mains.
We're working with AC/DC
because it's heavy metal.
(WHIRRING)
We're going to turn on
the current now,
so get ready to take down
notes from the screen.
(BUZZING)
Did you see that?
The bolt of electricity
passed right through the building.
Let's take a look outside.
An enormous pair of scissors
has appeared in the sky
directly above the laboratory.
And after a few moments...
..it's gone.
It's an old experiment
that you've probably seen before,
but well worth trying nonetheless.
Now hand in your copybook
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at flowers.