And now on BBC2, it's time to take
our weekly look into the future,
as we join Peter, Jack, Pam and
Pealy in London's Shepherd's Bush
for tonight's edition of
Look Around You.
Hello. Coming up
on tonight's programme...
we'll be unveiling
a brand-new sport.
We'll also be hosting
a unique sporting event,
right here in the studio, whoa!
And attempting to break
a world record.
That's all on tonight's
sporting edition of Look Around You.
Take it away, Brian.
♪ Look Around You ♪
(Commentator)
Oh, would you look at this!
Charging through the competition
with an incredible burst of energy,
Ros Lamb, the Southport Sparrow,
surges through to become
the world 400,000 metres champion!
There she is, being congratulated by
her husband and trainer, Ron Lamb,
Oh! She's overcome so much,
this girl, to get here today,
and now, brave Ros Lamb
is the pride of Roast Britain!
Wow!
Who can forget
that incredible victory?
- So inspirational!
- Fantastic!
And here she is to tell us about
a remarkable breakthrough
in running technology - Ros Lamb.
- Ros, welcome to Look Around You.
- Hello.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- Hi, Ros, hello.
- It's lovely to meet you.
- Hello.
Now, Ros, first of all,
congratulations once again.
Thanks.
You've brought your medal
to show us.
I have, yeah.
(Gasps)
- It's beautiful.
- Well done.
Now, Ros has run some pretty
impressive distances in her career,
but now she's able to run further,
and much faster than ever before.
And it's all thanks to this -
a serum, known as
di-tutetamine brohohibe.
Ros, tell us a bit about it.
Well, di-tutetamine brohohibe
is a new form of rocket fuel.
- Rocket fuel?
- Yeah.
Which has been flavoured
with caramel.
And there's also a savoury version,
available soon.
- It's been adapted for human use?
- Yeah, that's right, yeah
Now, Ros, tell us, what speed
can an average runner achieve?
Well, er, an Olympic sprinter
can reach about 20 miles an hour.
And how fast can you run using
di-tutetamine brohohibe?
About three and a half thousand
miles an hour, give or take.
Well, that's a pretty big increase.
Well, we're really going to put Ros
to the test now,
because we've devised a special
Look Around You challenge for her.
Ros is going to attempt
to run from here,
BBC Television Centre in London,
all the way to our studio
in Aberdeen,
where she'll be met by BBC
Scotland's Mario Abdullah-Levy.
- Hello Mario!
- Hello Peter!
Mario, tell us, just how far away
are you up there?
Well, we're 524 miles away
from Shepherd's Bush,
so it's a fair old distance.
And I have to tell you, Ros, that
it's absolutely freezing up here.
And although
I'd love to see it myself,
I hope you're not wearing anything
too skimpy!
(Laughs) Thanks Mario. Now, Ros
reckons she can run the distance
in just under five minutes.
Five minutes, yeah.
Well, you might want
a look at this first.
Thanks, I think I know the way.
Well, best of luck!
Ros is just taking
her di-tutetamine brohohibe.
And now we'll just wait
for the serum to take its effect.
(Heartbeat)
(Jet engine)
Ah! Oh!
Whoa!
Eddie! Eddie!
Mario! Thanks Eddie!
Mario, hopefully we'll see
you and Ros in about five minutes.
I can't quite hear
what you're saying,
but hopefully Ros and I will see you
in about five minutes.
And it's neck and neck for Grandma's
Ghost and Victim of Circumstance,
but he's having none of it.
And it's a mighty win
for Victim of Circumstance.
Another 50 quid down the drain.
Most of us enjoy a good flutter
every now and then,
but perhaps not the heartache
of losing.
So a system that could predict
the winner every time
would be a very attractive, not
to mention lucrative, proposition.
There are a number of betting
systems around at the moment,
the most famous being
the Lombard system,
which is not particularly reliable,
and is also quite tricky to use.
But now, there's a new system
that's said to be 100 per cent
accurate at predicting the winner.
And to hear about it, we have to go
straight to the horse's mouth.
That's because its inventor is,
in fact, a horse.
Please welcome Championess
and her owner, Paul Alan.
Whoa! Hey.
- Welcome, both of you.
- Hello.
Now, Paul,
Championess actually designed the
betting system - how did she do it?
Well, erm, I first noticed that
she was up to something when, er,
she locked herself away
in her stable for about six months.
Erm, occasionally I'd hear
the odd banging noise,
erm, but I just thought,
"Best leave her to it, really".
One day the stable doors were flung
open and there was her machine.
- And this is it.
- Yes.
She made it from stuff she found
lying around her stable.
And, as you can see, it's all
held together with her manure.
I see.
Sorry, animals and children,
they say, don't they? There we go.
- Indeed. Yes.
- And how does it work?
I tell her the names of the horses,
don't I, darling? That's right.
and the odds, the form...
- Come forward a little bit.
- ..maybe the size of the jockeys.
Then she types all the information
into her machine with her hoof.
- I see. Right, yeah.
- Yeah.
And then, a little bit later,
she gets the result.
She's been doing pretty well
from it, haven't you, darling?
Now, Championess has won 60,000
guineas this season alone.
And, Paul, may I ask,
what does she spend her winnings on?
Oh, the usual things -
hay, a new saddle,
carrots, sugar lumps.
I suppose the only luxury
she's allowed herself was a Jacuzzi.
But she only got in it the once.
I don't think she liked the bubbles!
Right.
Well, we're going to try out
Championess's system,
right here on the programme.
(Laughs) Pongo!
Obviously there's not enough room in
the studio for a live horse race,
is there, Championess?
So, we've got the next best thing -
ants.
And we'll be holding our very own
Look Around You Ant Derby later on,
which should give Championess just
enough time to study the runners.
We can now go back to BBC Scotland
and rejoin Mario Abdullah-Levy.
- Hello, Peter
- Hello, Mario.
Any sign of Ros Lamb?
Not yet, Peter, but we're
expecting her any second now.
- (Whooshing)
- In fact I can just hear....
She's arrived! She's here!
Stop the clock.
Four minutes
and twenty-eight seconds.
And that smashes the previous record
of 22 days, 3 hours and 15 minutes.
That's a new world record.
So Ros, how are you feeling?
Ros is understandably pretty well
worn out after her 524-mile run.
And as you can see, she's quite
a bit smaller than when she started.
That's due to a massive increase
in her body temperature
from travelling
at such a great speed.
And now, back to Peter Packard
at Television Centre.
Thanks, Mario. Yes, outstanding.
Hopefully we'll be hearing from Ros
once she's had a chance
to catch her breath.
Now, question - what do these
four footballers have in common?
Think you know?
Well, the obvious answer
is that they're all deaf,
but you may not know that they
all had footballs made for them
by one of soccer's unsung heroes -
the world's greatest football
designer, Sebastian Jackson.
During his career, Sebastian Jackson
produced some of the most innovative
and ingenious footballs ever,
including the controversial
Invisiball.
Jackson himself
was a flamboyant figure,
and was linked romantically
to a string of glamorous women,
including Marilyn Monroe's sister,
Margaret.
Unfortunately, Sebastian Jackson
passed away last year,
after swallowing a pin. He was 62.
However, with typical flair,
he took the precaution
of creating several copies,
or clones, of himself
before he died.
And we're very lucky to be joined
by one of them tonight -
please welcome Provastian Jackson.
- Hello, Jack.
- Hello, welcome to Look Around You.
You're an exact copy of the original
Sebastian Jackson, aren't you?
- Yes, I am.
- And how many of you are there?
Well, there's Ninastian, Compastian,
Hairhastain, Fantastian,
Clilthrastian,
and Torvartian,
who's our leader in a way.
I understand Ninastian
is with us tonight.
Yes, he is, he's over there.
- He's a little camera-shy.
- Oh well. Now, Provastian,
there haven't been any Jackson
footballs in the shops for a while.
No, but me and the other copycats
have been busy developing
a new range.
Let's take a look. Now, this first
football here, I have to say -
I'm not the best at football
by the way -
looks like any football
I might find lying about my garage.
Yes, it does look pretty ordinary,
I agree, but if you look at the top,
just press that button.
So, when you want to put it away,
it'Il fit neatly on your shelf
without rolling off.
We call it a footcube.
How does it work?
It's a mixture of pistons, springs
and Gary Bonds, very clever.
It is clever.
Now, this one over here,
please don't take this the wrong
way, but it does smell a bit.
- Pongo!
This is our meat-ball,
made from meat scraps
which would otherwise
just be thrown away.
It gently decomposes
during the course of the match.
So it's ecologically friendly.
Yes. Best not to use it in hot
weather - gets covered in maggots.
And it's all meat?
Well, there's a bit of cod
in this one.
Now, this jolly chap over here,
what is this?
- This is a piggyball.
- Piggyball?
Piggyball. You can see the slit
in the top.
- Mm-hm.
- (Coins jingle)
Used mainly for charity matches.
Now, this last one
looks extremely intriguing.
Just over here.
Well, this is our principal project
at the moment.
Its, erm...
Well, we... We've...
Do you know? Ninastian knows more
about this one than I do.
- OK.
- Ninastian.
Ninny, come on, Ninny!
(Jack) Well, I think we're going
to meet Ninastian Jackson now.
- Hello, Ninastian.
- Hello.
Tell him about it.
Oh, in order to create
a more aerdo...
aerodynamic football,
we designed an object
which is about 250 times more round
than a normal ball.
So what you're saying is you've
managed to out-round the sphere.
Unfortunately, we can't show
the football for legal reasons,
so I'll just have
to describe it to you.
Just please be careful you don't
pull the curtain back too far.
Don't worry.
Cor! That is extraordinary!
That is just so...round.
Well, the only way I can attempt
to describe it is,
if you can try to imagine a perfect
circle, and then round it out,
so that it's even rounder...
That is extraordinary. When can
we expect to see this in the shops?
Oh, that's a moot point actually,
because currently it's illegal
to sell it in this country,
as it does contain
a working human heart.
(Both) So It's only on sale in
Germany at the moment, I'm afraid.
Well, best of luck,
Provastian and Ninastian,
and thank you both
for showing us your balls. Peter.
And I believe we can go
to BBC Scotland
and rejoin Mario Abdullah-Levy,
who is now talking with Ros Lamb.
Ros, that was a terrific run,
London to Aberdeen in four and a
half minutes, a new world record.
(Squeaky voice) Thanks, yeah.
What happened to your forehead?
I ran into a parking meter
in Kilburn.
So after that
I just stuck to motorways.
So, a smooth journey?
Well, I got pulled over
a couple of times by the police.
- Oh really?
- Nothing serious, just a caution.
But in general, it was
a very good run, I'm very pleased.
Well, Maseltov once again.
And now Ros Lamb will be running
back down to our studios in London,
so Ros, if you'd like to take
your di-tutetamine brohohibe.
- And best of luck!
- (Squeaky voice) Thanks!
(Jet engine rumbles)
(Heartbeat)
Dougal!
And back to you, Peter,
at Shepherd's Bush.
When the Olympics take place next
year in Swansea Industrial Park,
there'll be a record number
of new events
which have been formally accepted
by the Olympic Committee
and Swansea Council.
In fact there are a staggering
22 brand-new Olympic sports,
but there's one sport
everyone wants to play.
So Look Around You sent Pealy Maghti
off to our sister country, America,
to try it out.
(♪ Pounding rock music)
(Pealy) Pennsylvania, USA.
When you think of Pennsylvania,
you probably think of pencils.
But in America, Pennsylvania
is best known for its baseball team,
the Pennsylvania Pippins.
And every Monday and Wednesday,
thousands of fans flock to see such
baseball legends as TJ Nottingham,
Sonny Thompson,
and Xythantiops.
But it's not just baseball that's
put Pennsylvania on the map.
Jogging recently
became compulsory here,
with stiff penalties for anyone who
doesn't fulfil the weekly mileage.
But now,
there's a new sport in town,
which may be about to take
the state, and the world, by storm.
So I caught up with its inventor,
Scott Nolan.
This sport you've created
isn't completely new, is it?
Not exactly, Pealy, no.
You see, I wanted to combine key
aspects of my two favourite sports,
into a new hybrid, or combo-sport,
which I believe has the potential
to become the most exciting
spectator sport at the Olympics.
What are the two sports
that you've combined?
Tennis and golf.
Well, I'm dying to try it out.
Now, am I dressed for the occasion?
I hope so, let's see,
you've got the shoes and the socks,
the pants, the hat...
All you need is this...
and you're all set!
Let's play gonnis!
Gonnis is a perfect mixture
of golf and tennis.
The rules are very simple -
get the ball over the net, onto the
green and into your opponent's hole,
whilst avoiding the bunkers
and the water hazard.
The game was overseen by the world's
only professional gonnis umpire,
Bunny Gnowles, who also happens
to be Scott's boyfriend.
- Go easy on me, Scott!
- Not a chance!
With its classy blend
of elegance and style,
gonnis has become the game of choice
for the jet set,
with such players as Manhattan Dave
and the Shah of Israel,
and Scott even had an order
for 40,000 gonnis sets
from none other than Tony Curtis.
Quiet, please!
Birdie-love.
- I'm getting the hang of this!
- We'll see about that.
Out! Quiet, please!
Eagle - 15.
(Softly) Come on, Scott, come on.
- Advantage, Miss Maghti.
- Go on, Pealy!
- Quiet, please!
Tensions ran high,
both on and off the court.
Ma'am, did you not hear me
say "quiet" then?
It's (bleep) off-putting
to the players,
it's (bleep) off-putting to the
opponent who you're not rooting for,
it's a (bleep) for him and for me!
And if you continue, I'm gonna
(bleep) remove you from the court.
Do you understand? Thank you.
(Bleep)
Miss Maghti, you are four under par.
Finally, it was time for me to put
my putting skills to the test.
- (Woman) Go on, Pealy!
- (Bleep)
Hole, set and match, Pealy Maghti.
I'd done it! Against all odds, I'd
beaten the American at his own game.
- That was fantastic!
- Yes, beginner's luck.
Miss Maghti, congratulations.
You played a good game.
Quiet, please.
Where now for Scott Nolan?
I'm developing another combo-sport
at the moment.
Again, it's a mixture
of two other sports -
fencing and darts.
Gosh, you were really good
at gonnis!
Thanks. And the funny thing is, I've
never played golf or tennis before.
- And I was on my period.
- Obviously a natural.
- Yes, well done, Pealy.
- Yeah, well played.
- Thanks, chaps.
- That is a beautiful trophy.
Well, we're just waiting for
Ros Lamb to speed into the studio
all the way from Aberdeen,
and I believe she should be here
any second now.
Well, while we're waiting
for Ros, erm...
Oh, and I believe we're now seeing
outside Television Centre,
where Ros Lamb should be speeding
into view any second now.
Erm, Jack, I believe you used to
go out with Ros Lamb, didn't you?
(Jack) Yes,
it was several years ago
and I used to fool around
with one of her sisters as well.
(Pealy) Not at the same time I hope!
(Peter) Here she is!
That's four minutes
and fifteen seconds.
That smashes her previous record,
by, I think, thirteen seconds,
so that's another world record.
- Erm, well done!
- Wow!
- Congratulations!
- Two in one show.
Well, let's go and say hello.
Ros, a new world record -
how do you feel?
(Panting)
(Peter) As you can see,
the run has really taken its toll,
there's been some further
miniaturisation.
Anyway, well done, Ros!
(Peter) What an athlete!
Well, now it's time
for our Look Around You Ant Derby.
And to tell us about the runners,
let's hand over to BBC's racing
commentator, Leslie Maxwell.
Thank you, in lane one at 5-1,
we have Beetleface,
looking very confident today.
In lane two, one of
our foremost racing ants, Mr Snips,
the favourite at 3-1.
Fancy Nancy is in lane three,
the going's a bit hard for her
today, I fear, she's at 7-1.
And finally,
the rank outsider, Nutmeg,
who looks like he's put on a bit of
weight recently, he's at 600-1.
- Back to you, Pam
- Thanks.
- Well, my money's on Beetleface.
- I fancy... Fancy Nancy.
I'm going to take a chance on
Nutmeg. How about you, Pete?
Yeah, me too.
And Ros, who will you be backing?
(High-pitched squeaking)
One pound on Mr Snips,
certainly Ros.
And there we are!
(Faint squeaking continues)
So, Paul, Championess has had time
to make her calculations.
Can we have her prediction, please?
(Paul) Go on, girl!
(Mechanical whirring)
- Is she finished?
- Yes.
So, which ant does Championess think
is going to win?
(Deep voice) Beetleface.
Beetleface!
Oh, that's my ant, great!
So, let's go back to Leslie
for the race.
Thanks, Pam. You join us
for the Look Around You Ant Derby,
all the ants are
at the starter's gate.
(Trumpet fanfare)
And they're off! Mr Snips
off to a good start, Nutmeg refuses,
Beetleface coming up,
Fancy Nancy picking up speed,
But it's Mr Snips and Beetleface,
they're thorax to thorax,
but it's Beetleface the winner!
- Yeah!
- Oh!
- I win!
- Well done!
- Bad luck, guys!
And well done and thank you very
much to Paul Alan and Championess.
And Championess and Paul Alan
go through to the final
of our Invention of the Year
competition
at the end of the series,
where they could win
this magnificent trophy,
presented by His Royal Highness
Sir Prince Charles.
Well, that's nearly all
we've got time for tonight.
Thanks to all our guests
for being such great sports.
- Thank you to Provastian and...
- I'm Ninastian.
- Oh, I beg your pardon.
- Provastian's dropped off.
Well, thank you to you both,
and also, of course,
thanks to Ros Lamb.
(Squeaks)
Special thanks to BBC Scotland
and Mario Abdullah-Levy.
And thanks to racing commentator,
Leslie Maxwell.
My pleasure, Pam.
And a special thanks to Beetleface,
Mr Snips, Fancy Nancy and Nutmeg.
Thanks, ants!
Thants.
Next week, we'll be taking
a tantalising look
at the world, and the future,
of food.
So make sure you make a reservation.
So, in the meantime, from all of us
here at Shepherd's Bush,
take care of yourself, and remember,
wherever you are, whatever you do...
(All) Look Around You!
(All chatter)
♪ Look Around You ♪