How long
do we have to wait?
Until we catch
our bad guy.
Can I sleep?
You can't sleep
on a stakeout, Shawn.
You can eat. You can chew gum.
But you can't drink because if you
drink, you're gonna have to pee.
And the target always comes
out right when you got to pee.
Now I think I gotta pee.
Well, then, Shawn, your bladder is
going to get some training tonight, too.
We've got action.
Now, I want you to stay down.
I know, I know, I know.
Go! Go!
Come on.
I got you. I got you red-handed,
you lying son of a bitch.
"I don't know what happening to your
newspaper, Henry." You're transparent, Clark.
You didn't think
I could nab a liar like you?
I can explain!
Tell it to the Neighborhood
Watch Association.
Give the paper
to the boy, Clark.
What the hell are you doing?
Checking baseball scores.
My fantasy team is killing me.
This is the Chief's office!
I know, she runs the league.
I'm kidding.
She's in a meeting.
She won't mind.
Plus, we look really important
hanging out in here.
Gus, have you
tried this chair?
It's a pregnancy chair.
We have gotta get one
for the office immediately.
My birthing canal
has never felt so in line.
We need to get out of
here. She told me to wait.
For what?
Gus, I'm not a mind reader.
No, that's just
what you tell everybody.
I want you to try this chair.
I'm not
trying that chair, Shawn.
I'll sit on
the birthing ball.
I kid you not, that thing is
like a refreshing waterfall
cascading down your vertebrae.
It might help
with your stomach issues.
Who told you
I had stomach issues?
My nose?
The vent in the bathroom? Air
fresheners all over the place?
I'm trying a new medication
for my lactose intolerance.
I believe
the problem is physical.
And I think it can be cured
by what I'm now referring to as
the magic springy
bounce-up chair.
Hey, Shawn,
smoothies are here.
Pineapple?
Of course.
Thanks, Buzz.
You're having food delivered?
They were already
going out.
Oh, boy. I'm telling you...
Wow.
What did I tell you?
Now, take a hit off this bad boy and
complete the moment, you've earned it.
What do you think
this is, Mr. Guster?
I apologize. This will never
happen again. Give me that.
Boys, out!
What is this, Gus, a smoothie?
You know these things stain.
Mmm. But they
are very delicious.
Chief, would you like some?
That's not my smoothie.
I don't care
whose smoothie it is.
I don't even remember
why I asked you to stay now.
You want us on that case
with the blonde woman. No.
Mmm-hmm, Wintersby,
Wilacheck, Wislerbottom?
No, no, it's...
Wilcroft?
No, that's not...
Okay, wait a minute,
were you listening in
on my conversation?
I don't know
if I heard it psychically
or if I saw you walk by with
her and Detective Lassiter,
but I definitely heard
the word "psychic."
The woman, Raylene, said she
visits an occasional psychic.
She wasn't asking for one.
Well, not in so many words.
No, not in any words.
This is a bank robbery case. We don't
need psychics for a bank robbery case.
Bank robbery?
Mmm-hmm.
I didn't read anything in the
paper about a bank robbery.
It was four years ago.
So, it went unsolved?
It was solved.
Well, then what does she need
a psychic for?
Gus, that is a perfectly
reasonable question.
Thank you, Chief.
We'll be leaving now.
I'm sorry, I'm
sorry. I'm still confused.
Her husband's partners are
getting out of jail.
This is a routine warning that we issue
when someone may potentially be in danger.
This is the part where
we offer up our services.
No, I think this is the
part where we leave.
That's a good idea.
But... Believe
it or not, Mr. Spencer,
crimes were solved
long before you got here.
And they continue to be solved
when you're not around.
Oh, I remember what I
wanted to tell you. What?
Stay out of my chair.
Bank robbers?
Dude, that's awesome.
We should go find Lassiter and
our future client. We gotta go.
Dude, this woman is on an eternal
quest for a good psychic? That's me!
I'm gonna go find them.
I'm staying right here.
Great idea. Wait ten seconds,
and make an entrance. Drink some.
Are you saying
that I'm in danger?
Your husband's partners
are being paroled today.
I have reason to believe
their first order of business
is gonna be to try
and find that lost money.
But the only person who knew where
that money ended up was my husband.
I know that.
But do they?
Hey, Lassi.
Juliet.
Oh, I don't believe we've met.
Or did we meet?
In a bank?
No, that's not it.
Why am I getting "bank"?
Piggy bank?
Sperm bank?
Doesn't matter.
I'm Shawn Spencer.
I am the official head psychic
here at the department.
You don't
have a title.
And there is serious doubt as to
whether you're really even psychic.
I solved the McCallum
disappearance.
And the Summerland murder.
Oh, and I found your keys.
And your badge.
Out.
Shawn, where are my keys?
No. Out!
If you don't mind, we're a
little busy. We have a...
Excuse us, Raylene.
Do we know each other?
No, we don't. I'm sorry.
Psychic, remember? Sometimes
I can't turn it off.
Do you do readings?
Yes, we do it all.
Full service.
I'm a bit of an enthusiast. I used
to have a regular girl read for me.
Really?
Here's a card.
We're at the
beachfront location.
I could put my cell number on the
back if you have any questions.
Any time, really.
Thank you,
you're so kind.
This is a
pharmaceutical company.
Like I said,
we do it all.
Well, I always say,
"A man with many hats..."
"Doesn't like his haircut"?
Exactly. I thought I was the
only one who read that book.
It's my favorite.
Mine, too.
Really?
And scene!
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Dude, what took you so long?
This is good stuff. You gotta
see what happened to this car.
I mean, it was really...
What?
What happened here?
Oh, that?
Oh, I had a drywaller
come in and take out a wall.
A wall?
This is a rental! What do you
think our landlord is gonna say?
Gee, I don't know,
"Thank you"?
Gus, this place
was way too cramped.
My name is on that lease.
Don't worry, I'll make sure
you get a thank you note, too.
You're taking my name off the lease.
And the door, and these Frisbees.
Gus, don't be ridiculous.
Look, I'm almost positive
this isn't a load-bearing wall.
But if you're really concerned, why don't
you go jump up and down in the attic
and make sure?
What is she doing here?
Ah, she's our
first real client.
Actually client?
Hired for the job?
Actual client.
Go on, man.
I have to admit, when I met you at
the police station, I was intrigued,
so I checked
your recent track record.
It's amazing, really.
Well, it's a team effort.
Not really.
I do most of the work.
What can we
help you with, ma'am?
I need you to get
in contact with someone.
Well, tracking people down
is our specialty.
What? Oh, it's not, now?
This one might
be a little tricky.
How tricky? Is the person
out of the state? Country?
He's dead.
Ah, and I assume that's
why you need a psychic.
Hold on. Dead?
Like dead, dead?
Currently being
eaten by worms?
He's actually entombed
in a mausoleum.
Gus, he's ascended to the
next dimension. It's fine.
No, Shawn, I think we might be
at a bit of an impasse.
What exactly do you
need to know?
My husband was not
a perfect man.
He got himself
in a bit of trouble.
Okay, I'll be honest,
it was a lot of trouble.
He got involved
in a bank robbery.
He was one of three, but the
only one who didn't go to prison.
Unfortunately, the reason
he didn't get caught
was that he drove his car
down an embankment...
Wait.
I see rain.
No roads, no.
There was a fiery crash,
wasn't there?
Yes.
What would you
like me to ask, Raylene?
Well, this is hard to say.
But he was the one
designated to bury the money.
They were to all meet later
and divide the cash.
Only his partners
were caught first.
So why wait until now?
His partners think that
I know where he hid the money.
If I don't give it to them,
they're gonna kill me.
Shawn, can I
speak to you outside, please?
I guess.
Dude, what is wrong with you?
Shawn, I don't know how to break
this to you, but you are not psychic.
Clue me in
on the problem here.
It's a big problem when the job requires
extensive conversing with the dead.
Gus, what is the question
that she wants answered?
Where is the money, right?
That doesn't require
any actual dead guy chitchat.
We simply trace his last
steps, do a little research,
ask a few questions,
and bingo!
Stop saying "bingo."
You know how I hate that.
Okay, fine. Yahtzee.
We're not doing it, Shawn.
Mahjong. Gus!
Mrs. Wilcroft.
Raylene.
Your problem is
outside of our reach.
You are in real danger.
I'd like to recommend
police protection.
I'm pleased
to be of service.
Thank you.
I know they're in there.
Just so you know, I am uncomfortable
with inter-office romance.
I wasn't considering it.
And I'm completely uncomfortable
with the implication.
So, it wasn't true, the rumor
about you and your last partner?
I'm not going to dignify
that with a response.
- This is them.
- The bank robbers?
Yeah, a little worse for the
wear than the day I arrested them.
You caught them?
I was part of a team,
but, yeah, it was mostly me.
That's a big deal.
Would've been a big deal if I had
found the money and closed the case.
Things like that
make a career.
Instead, I got a bunch
of loose ends, a dead guy,
and 3.6 million in cash
that vanished into thin air.
It's funny,
they don't look so mean.
What do you mean "mean"?
They look like repairmen.
Big repairmen, but they
don't look like killers.
Duck!
Eyes of a serpent,
ears of a bat.
Send us a signal from...
Shawn.
I hear a voice.
Can I see you outside, please?
It wants me to come outside.
Now?
I should go.
Is that my bathrobe?
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm
doing? I'm having a séance.
You can't have a séance!
Gus, there are no rules against
having a séance. Anyone can have one.
It's like a garage sale.
Or plastic surgery.
Okay, first of all,
technically,
you need to have a permit
to have a garage sale.
Secondly, you cannot
speak to the dead.
Oh, Gus, you don't
understand at all, do you?
I don't need to make contact
with the dead.
No, I need to speak with
all the people in that room.
They're witnesses.
We can piece together the rest based
on the information they give us.
I'm already on to something.
Check this out.
The dead guy was on the lam for three
days with the cash. He had help.
From whom?
I'm almost there.
Raylene?
Yes, Shawn?
I'm sensing the last time he
called before the accident.
Ellen was the only
one who talked to him.
Ellen. Yes,
I feel that deeply.
You didn't tell
the police that, did you?
No, I was afraid. He's my brother.
I didn't want to turn him in.
No, of course not.
Where did he call from?
A pay phone outside a store.
Yes, it was a store,
I feel it. Which store?
I think it was a...
Thriftymart.
Up north. He'd been driving.
I've always imagined
it was the one near Pismo.
Pismo! Yes, but
the spirits are confused,
they need more
specific directions.
Nearest cross street?
Just past the park
we used to hike with Roger.
Who's Roger?
He's our cousin.
Really?
But wait, there's more.
The spirits are asking me.
What is Roger's address?
I really haven't
seen Roger in years.
Come on, Ellen!
Work with me! Think harder.
Okay, sorry.
How about a phone number?
Okay.
Gus, what have you done? You've
broken the chain of spiritual trust.
I didn't break anything.
Don't ruin it
for everyone, Gus.
I'm not ruining anything.
Listen, Raylene,
I have to apologize to you.
You seem like
a very decent person.
But what you need
is protection, not this.
A bodyguard, a policeman.
I can assure you,
there is no spirit in here.
What?
And let me make you a guarantee,
there is absolutely no way
there will be any sort
of contact with zombies...
You okay?
I think that's all
for tonight, ladies.
Did you do that?
Why would I ruin
our totally cool window?
For effect,
to make me think
you contacted an evil ghost.
Gus, please.
Why didn't you float that idea
by me sooner? That's genius.
Somebody obviously
wants us off this case.
I think
it's those convicts.
But whoever it is,
we'll never find them.
I just saw them run off.
You sure about that?
Yeah.
Ladies, stay here.
We're going after them.
Or it.
Let's get some tacos.
Okay.
And then the window
just shattered.
And you think ghosts did it?
No. No. No.
Though there may have been some women
present who thought ghosts were responsible.
I blame it on the two convicts
from the Holmby Bank robbery.
I'm sorry, I still don't
understand why that means
you need to see
the entire case file.
Oh, no, no, Juliet, we don't
need to see the whole thing. No.
No, just the cover page, one
or two others, here, there.
Definitely the witness list.
Well, you gotta see that.
And the Chief's okay
with this? Oh, yeah.
I don't think so.
No?
No.
I liked the other girl better.
Not me.
Hey, since we're here,
we should do some digging.
Good idea, why don't you dig
me getting the hell out of here
and going to get some sleep?
Hey, I set you up for that.
Lobbed it right
over the plate.
Mr. Spencer!
Oh!
Hey, you, what a surprise.
You look different.
Yes, I took your advice.
Three weeks
without a cigarette.
Well, it has certainly
enhanced your aura.
And remember,
it wasn't my advice,
it was your grandma's spirit.
Have you spoken to her again?
She's here.
Now?
Yes.
Where? In this hallway?
No.
In the records room.
I thought I felt
something eerie in there.
Me, too. Unfortunately,
I'm not allowed down there.
Please.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Not too much light.
You don't want to
scare her away.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
Yes, I can feel her,
all right.
She's...
She's over by the W's.
Why?
No. W.
This is it!
I'm nervous.
Don't be.
I want you to relax. Breathe.
Close your eyes.
Why would she be in the W's?
I don't know.
Did you know any W's?
That bastard Walter.
Walter.
Your ex?
Wow! Yes.
I hear something.
Yes, me, too.
Paper.
No, it's not paper.
Yes, it's clearly paper.
You have to concentrate.
Breathe deeply.
No, uh-uh.
I'm definitely not
feeling anything anymore.
I think we've lost her.
I'm so sorry
I couldn't reach her.
It's okay. I know how temperamental
the spirit world can...
Your hand!
Oh!
It was the spirits!
Yes.
It's a message from beyond.
What does it say?
I think I should keep it to
myself. It's a private message.
Dude, you look so peaceful
when you're sleeping.
Never come in my apartment
again. You hear me?
I've seen
the Holmby Bank file.
Look, Shawn, I don't want
to... The cousin is the key.
Which cousin? The one
the sister mentioned?
And then immediately regretted.
You could see it. She let it slip.
Dude, the guy runs a cemetery.
Which one? Oh, I don't know, the
one David Wilcroft is buried in?
I'll bet you dollars to donuts he
knows exactly where the money is.
Look, it's all right here
on my hand.
His name is Roger Blaine,
creepy as all get-out.
Lives on the grounds,
alone, no wife, no kids.
Not that part. That's the Italian
seamstress I met at the Renaissance fair.
How much further
is this place?
I don't know,
50, 60 miles.
60 miles!
And you didn't get me a donut?
I did get you a donut.
Then I ate it.
I can't believe
I'm doing this.
Solving a crime? That happens
to be our job description.
No, driving so far on a whim.
A whim, he says. A guy dies and
gets buried by his own weirdo cousin
in a tiny cemetery way up the coast
in a town with a population of 200.
That is not a whim,
that is a clue.
You think the
cousin has the money?
Roger Blaine? That even
sounds like an alias.
He could've killed Wilcroft. Or
it could have been the sister.
Gus, they're all
kind of creepy.
The dead guy, the undertaker,
the sister, Raylene.
Oh, there's nothing
creepy about Raylene.
Nothing creepy about the
melodramatic widow? No.
Are you serious?
Who marries a bank robber?
Who sees a psychic every week?
There's nothing wrong
with her, Shawn. Okay.
What is this thing you have
with women in jeopardy?
They have a name for this, you know.
It's called the Stockholm syndrome.
No, it's not.
Florence Nightingale's
disease?
Are you trying to be funny? You can't
ridicule me because I want to help.
I can when you want
to help too much.
You have an unnatural affinity for this woman
that I simply cannot wrap my brain around.
She dresses like she's
on her way to a PTA meeting.
Fine. She reminds me of somebody
who was very important to me.
Who?
Don't worry about it.
Oh, no.
What?
Don't say it.
Don't say Meredith Baxter
Birney! It's not MBB!
This is unhealthy. Okay, you
were in love with her, too.
I loved her because she was Mrs.
Keaton, and she gave birth to APK.
It's not her anyway.
Well, who is it?
My babysitter.
Your babysitter.
Yes, my babysitter.
Gus, Mrs. Pilderman
was in her late 60s.
Mrs. Pilderman was 37 years
old and she was a nurse, Shawn.
She taught me things, like, you know,
about books and art. Things like that.
Things like skinny-dipping? I did not
go skinny-dipping with Mrs. Pilderman!
Well, at least that sheds
some light on it.
Huh, nobody's home.
No, somebody's here.
You can see through doors now,
that's the new thing?
I can smell the laundry
vent. No, you can't.
Okay.
Oh, Gus, please with the
supersmeller. You have to stop!
Oh, dude, I can smell it, too.
I told you.
Jeans and socks and underwear
and a Bounce sheet.
Make jokes. How long do you think
it takes to dry a load of clothes?
Thirty minutes? Somebody's
here and not answering the door.
Gus, I apologize.
That's very
impressive detective work.
I feel a little bad about the
donut thing now. You should.
Dang it!
Let's try the back.
Just stay
and watch. Go on, G.
Whoa!
You're not Roger!
No, no, you're...
You're David Wilcroft.
Aren't you
supposed to be dead?
Gus?
Look. It's not that easy
to explain.
I'm not a real criminal. I just...
I got in a little over my head.
You robbed a bank.
I didn't want to.
I was in a bad place.
They trusted me. I was
supposed to stash the cash.
You lost the money.
Yeah. How'd you know?
It was raining. Really
hard, for two whole days.
It was the worst rainstorm
in 30 years.
You couldn't find it.
Yeah. By the time
the roads reopened,
every marker I left was gone,
it was washed away.
I lost three and a half
million dollars.
Driving back,
I nearly drove off the road.
It was then I realized
I'd be better off dead.
And you have been
digging ever since.
Every chance I can get out there
without the risk of being seen
by hikers or
mountain bikers, I dig.
You know what? Raylene
is in agony over this.
I didn't mean her any harm.
You were never gonna
tell her? I couldn't.
Excuse us a moment.
What?
Gus, what's happening with you
and this guy's wife?
Are you having
feelings for this woman?
That's ridiculous. No, no,
Gus. Gus, this is wonderful.
Look, we didn't know he was alive. When she
came to us she was technically available.
Shawn. Stop it. I'm not
hitting on your wife.
No, he's not. But there's some
serious crushing going on here.
Dude, I am not blind. "A man with
many hats doesn't like his haircut"?
What book is that from?
She's a charming woman.
A charming woman?
Oh, you're Jane Austen now?
She's an adult, she is
attractive, she's mature.
Shawn... David, help me out here,
tell him that this is healthy.
Raylene is a
very dynamic woman.
Everybody is drawn to her.
Look, guys,
I know you want to turn me in. But you gotta
understand I'm close. I am so very close.
I've covered nearly every inch inside
the Kalish trail loop where I buried it.
And you want us
to let you find it?
Get her to hide someplace,
someplace safe.
I just want to return the
money and get on with my life.
Hmm?
We have to think
this through. Yeah.
You know, in my mind,
they were the lucky ones,
they got to go to prison, pay
off their debt to society.
I've been living
as a dead man.
If Raylene's going to
find out that I'm alive,
at the very least, don't let it come
from a stranger, let it come from me.
We're letting him go?
He's not going anywhere
until he finds that money.
I doubt that'll be
anytime soon.
He did have
cool hair, though.
God, we're missing
something else here!
He's the key
to solving this puzzle.
We need to tell Raylene.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. We're holding all the
cards here, Gus. Why would we do that?
Because she's in danger.
Maybe we can fix that.
Your husband, he's alive.
Gus! Remember the part where
we weren't going to tell her?
We never said that!
David's alive?
We found him.
He's with his cousin.
Roger? No, no, no.
That can't be.
I'm sure your head is spinning and that
you don't feel completely safe right now.
But rest assured,
we do have a plan.
We are gonna put
the convicts back in jail.
Where they belong. And are
gonna stay for a while.
We'll put these guys
behind bars, where they belong.
So who authorized
this stakeout?
What?
You know, who set it up?
I did.
I mean, who sanctioned it?
Approved it? Above you.
Above me? You know, I don't
think I like where this is going.
I just mean it should be officially
sanctioned as per the police code.
Which one?
11A-17.
Ticky-tack. Doesn't apply.
In most cases someone
still has to authorize it.
Oh, that's right,
I remember now. I did!
Well, what about 42.211?
What about it?
Well, it states that...
It's superseded by 15.75.
Not necessarily.
If you're in the
jurisdiction of a 23.40, it is.
Maybe.
Maybe?
Technically, a 23.40 only
applies in federal cases.
What are you doing in here?
I thought we could share info.
What are we looking at?
Get the hell out of my car!
Shouldn't you be wondering how I slid in and
lounged for two minutes without you noticing?
You're new and pretty,
so it's okay.
You've got ten seconds
before I latch the doors and
haul you down to the station.
They don't know where
the money is. What?
Isn't that why you're following them?
So they'll lead you to the money?
Psychic. It's amazing.
You'll get used to it.
Look, the dead guy buried the money and
then lost it, but that's beside the point.
I think we can cut our losses, put those
two back behind bars, if we work together.
And how do we do that?
Well, first, we dress up as musketeers
and make a very special pact.
Come on, you've watched them pull at
least a handful of probation violations.
You've been tailing them. You
saw what they did to my office.
They haven't been anywhere
near your office.
They were near enough to bust out my
window two nights ago. No, you're wrong.
You lost them, anyway.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Bye, Juliet.
They don't want our help?
Of course they don't. But they also lost
our guys. Did you see where they went?
Did I see where they went? You mean did
I see their car turn right on Riverside?
Or did I see the parking tag
from the 2400 Motel?
Touché! Did you see what
kind of whiskey they bought?
Shawn, please.
Time is being wasted.
This is breaking
and entering.
No, no, no.
Only if we break something.
And then enter something.
Entering is just entering.
I'm not breaking
a law, Shawn.
Look, you wanna save
your little widow?
We've got to find some
evidence to put these guys away.
I'm standing firm on this.
Fine, what about the window?
If it just opens,
does that count?
Depends.
Ooh. Hey, I see something.
Shawn?
I might be able to slide
this chain off.
Shawn? Gus, I'm
trying to concentrate.
You might wanna turn
around. What? Whoa!
You guys parked
round back, huh?
Okay, okay!
Was that really necessary?
Were we resisting?
Man, window inspector?
In a motel?
Okay, I lied. I did.
I'm sorry.
The truth is I'm a psychic.
That's what I do. Perhaps you've
read about me in the paper recently.
I've been in jail four years.
You don't have papers?
I thought you guys had TV
and yard darts
and mahjong and...
Okay,
I come bearing a message
from a departed being.
David Wilcroft
wants you to know
that he lost the money.
It's gone forever.
Why you telling us this?
He is concerned
that you're going to harm
Rins... Racquel...
Raylene.
Oh, that's funny.
That is funny.
Jesse, can you make sure
that we are not disturbed?
You can...
Can you prove
you're a psychic?
Sure. Sure.
You are a bank robber.
Yes, you did not like prison.
You are wearing the same pants
that you were released in,
and you have packed
on a few pounds since being...
No, look, man, I'm talking
about real proof! Like a test.
Now, look, if you're right,
you live. If you're wrong...
Man, you don't
wanna be wrong.
Here's the thing. It's
not really a parlor trick.
No. And I
don't want to cheapen it.
Look, prove it now. Let's go.
What's wrong with you,
man? Move!
Okay! Okay!
How many fingers?
Are you kidding?
Do I look like I'm joking
around? How many fingers?
We gotta be able to come up
with something better than that.
All right, man. Time's up.
Four.
All right, how many now?
Two. Now can we move on?
Because Gus and I
have some questions that we...
Three. For instance,
why was it so funny...
Three.
And is it possible...
Still three.
Now it's technically
two and a half fingers.
And the guy with the gun
is flipping me the bird.
You can see my fingers,
can't you?
No. No.
Yes, yes, yes, I can.
It's the reflection of the TV bouncing
off the mirror to the water pitcher here.
All right. Okay, maybe not. We're
gonna try this one more time.
Now, how many fingers?
Dude, you need
to stop picking three.
Respect, man.
Gee. Oh, man! That's...
Yep. They're back here.
I can't believe we lost them.
Don't think
that wasn't on purpose.
To Wilcroft.
A hell of a wheel man.
He was the wheel man?
Yeah. You should
know that, right?
Well, Shawn's visions sometimes
are scattered. Incomplete.
How does a wheel man miss
a turn on a mountain road?
I tell you what,
he didn't miss that turn.
I bet he just drove straight
off. You wanna know why?
Because he was trying
to get away from his wife.
Damn, you're good.
No, no. That can't be,
why would he be...
We called her the Viper.
Man, she was cold as hell.
We had to do whatever she
said, man. We had no choice.
Who?
The wife.
Raylene?
You know her?
Well, she came to us,
she wanted to contact David.
Figures. That was
her only weakness.
The occult. Man, she'd stop at nothing
to get her hands on that money.
No, she only wanted the money
to protect herself from you two.
From us?
Yeah.
Man, the last thing
we would ever do is cross her.
All we wanted to do
was get away from her.
Especially David.
Man, she ran him around like he was
an animal. He did whatever she said.
Look, man, I don't know
if you guys got caught up
in the charm
or whatever,
but I'll tell you, man, that was
her key. She could play anybody.
I'm telling you
she is a very dangerous lady.
Raylene was the mastermind?
I already knew that.
Because I'm a psychic.
Come on, guys. We should go.
You don't want
to go out that way.
Why?
We got company outside.
Is there another
way out of here?
I can't believe I just
crawled through a bathroom window.
It has to be a lie.
Gus, you're attracted to
dangerous women, man. It happens.
Joan Jett, for example.
Penny Marshall.
Grace Jones.
Or the woman who played
Pinky Tuscadero.
She seemed so sincere.
So vulnerable, you know?
Yeah! Turns out she's
a domineering snake lady
who drove her browbeaten
husband to fake his own death.
And we, we led her right
to the poor bastard.
Lizzie Borden,
Kathy Bates!
Raylene! This is not you...
Whoa! What, today's gun day?
Sit.
"Just rush in here."
Bad idea, Shawn.
Let her hang herself.
Quiet.
Raylene, I am sensing that this
is going to end very, very badly.
Find me my money.
I know you have it.
He doesn't have it.
I'm the only one
who knows where the money is.
Whoa! He doesn't know
where the money is.
Of course I know
Shawn, I don't know what your strategy
is, but you don't know where the money is.
You have five seconds.
One...
Really? The countdown?
Two...
Three!
Okay, it's in the crypt!
The money's in the crypt?
Well, David here certainly
isn't. Think about it, Raylene.
Roger runs the place. It's
the perfect hiding spot.
They can get in and out
whenever they want.
Pry it open.
With what?
With the stanchion.
Apparently those are called stanchions,
Gus, were you aware of this?
Yes, I was.
How did you figure out that money
was in the crypt? I'm bluffing.
This is not a good
time to bluff!
I think it's a great time!
She was going to kill us.
And besides, I've always thought a crypt
was a great place to stash loot, you know?
It's kind of like a vault, I mean, you can
just get in there whenever you need to.
She's gonna figure
out you're lying.
Eventually. But, come on, it's gonna
take a while to bust open a crypt.
Wow. Not as long
as I was hoping for.
Help him get it out.
Raylene, please.
What are you waiting for?
That.
Son of a...
David?
I don't believe this.
Well, what are you going to
do, Raylene? Shoot all of us?
None of you are armed.
I can do whatever I want.
Really now?
Drop it.
You, move away
from the stanchion.
What took you so long?
Shut up!
He does have nice hair.
Yeah, that takes a lot of
upkeep, though, man.
Yeah. You gotta worry
about split ends...
Dandruff.
It's horrible.
It's awful.
Yeah. Let's get out of here.
The Wilcrofts are not talking
at all to our investigators.
We get indications from their lawyers that
they will plead the fifth to all charges,
which leaves me with a
whole slew of loose ends.
For instance,
Detective Lassiter,
could you tell me how you made the discovery
that David Wilcroft was still alive?
Well, actually, Chief, we never
made that connection, per se.
We were on a stakeout...
Yes, I see that.
You describe it
as "harrowing and intense."
I'm sorry,
those were my words.
You wanted me
to spell-check it.
I still don't understand how that
connected you to David Wilcroft.
Well, that's where we come in,
Chief, some good work was done...
By Detective Lassiter.
He was amazing.
He figured out there was
a connection to Roger Blaine,
the cousin, who was involved
with the faking of the death.
Burnt body, no DNA, pretty
convenient, he deducted.
I never said that.
No, but you thought it.
That's how good you are, Lassy.
You practically solved this entire case
up here without uttering a spoken word.
I did nothing of the kind. I was following
the money and protecting Raylene.
Who turned out
to be the dangerous one.
Which I picked up from Detective
Lassiter's massive brain.
Not true.
True.
Not.
It was so!
Gentlemen, please.
So we still have no idea
where the money is?
I got nothing from him. But if he figures
anything out I'll be the first to know.
Would you excuse us
for a moment?
We're going to have
a private conversation.
I know what you're doing.
Giving you credit? You're trying
to get me to admit you're psychic.
You've already done that.
No, I haven't.
You're right. I'm sorry,
you didn't actually say it.
Spencer, no matter what you do, I
will never, never ever say those words.
Which words?
You know which words.
No, man, I lost my train
of thought. Which words?
Oh,
that you think
I'm a psychic.
Those words?
So when are you going to
tell them where the money is?
I don't know
where the money is.
Sure you do.
You're seeing dirt.
Am I right?
No!
What am I going to say now?
What are we doing here?
It's Saturday, I thought
we'd get some fresh air.
We drove an hour out of town
to get some fresh air?
Well, there's that,
and we're gonna find the dread
pirate Wilcroft's dirty booty.
Shawn, the guy's been digging
for four years.
We're gonna find it
in one afternoon?
Ninety minutes. Tops.
And I brought some chicken
for a hearty snack.
And how do you
plan on finding it?
Well, he said he dug every inch of the
Kalish Loop after he buried it here. Right?
Yes. Three miles' worth.
But it was dark
and it had rained.
And he said he thought it was right
off the path, he may have gotten lost.
I heard the story, Shawn.
Did he realize there's a J.
Kalish and an L. Kalish trail?
Dude, it's completely defunct.
Check it out,
only used by the rangers for back fires,
medical access, mud slide emergency routes,
like, for instance,
during a torrential rainstorm.
Otherwise, it's gated and it looks
completely abandoned from the road.
Okay, I find it,
I get credit.
I'm the psychic,
I have to get a vibration.
"Chief?" "Yes?"
"I'm getting
a trailhead, a pathway.
"And something else."
"What is it?"
"Chicken bones.
"Yes, tandoori style.
"Fresh!" "Oh, I bet
they were delicious."
"Yes."
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know