You're dead, Spencer.
What you doing, Shawn?
Nothing.
Looks like something to me.
Okay. I was running away
from Ryan Brickhouse.
- That him?
Mmm-hmm.
Is he the same kid who's been
hassling you all week?
Yeah.
Why is he
chasing you today?
I might have thrown
a rock at him.
Did you hit him?
Almost.
Get back out there.
What?
You can't run away from the
bad guys forever, Shawn.
Eventually, you got to come up
with a new approach.
So?
So, find one.
You're flunking math?
Probably.
Here's the deal.
Leave me alone,
I'll make sure
you ace the test tomorrow.
How?
Every third answer is "C."
There's a pattern
to all our tests.
Mrs. Bodansky
does it every time.
I memorized it.
I'll show you.
You better not be lying.
Not bad. You faced your fears. You
got a new result. You came out ahead.
Did you really memorize
those test answers?
Yeah.
Who are you calling?
Your math teacher.
No, no,
no, no, no.
Yes. Yes.
Nickel. That's a nickel.
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Who is that?
Who is who?
The girl sitting
in our front desk.
Ah, you're talking
about the lovely Dagmar.
Dagmar? She's our
new receptionist.
How did she get the job?
Agency sent her over.
You contacted a temp agency
without consulting me?
Gus, anyone can get a
secretary from a temp agency.
It takes real foresight and creativity
to get one from a modeling agency.
A modeling agency?
Wow.
Now, why would a beautiful lady
like that want to be our secretary?
Oh, that's a bit
of a story, you see.
Apparently, she got it in her
head that this was a runway gig.
I blame the agent.
I was very clear on the phone.
But she's cool with sticking around for
the rest of the day and seeing how it goes.
You know how slow it gets
when it's not modeling season.
Does she answer the phone?
Yes. But only her cell phone.
She's expecting a call from Milan.
Does she file?
Mostly her nails.
Coffee?
Yes, she wants some.
Can I make you anything?
No.
Dude, I thought you weren't
coming in till, like, noon.
Big drama at the office today. A
doctor we supply product to got killed.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You didn't call me immediately?
You don't know him.
Gus, this is what we do.
Remember? We can solve the case.
The police are already there.
This means nothing to me. They're going
to need help, guidance, psychic vibrations.
Dagmar?
She doesn't speak English?
Does she need to?
Where in the name of all
that is holy is my forensics team?
All right, what can you
tell me about this doctor
that I can pretend to ascertain
from the spirit world?
Dr. Blinn wasn't
on my route.
I did cover him
a few times.
All I remember is
he always made you wait
and he had a picture
of Pete Rose on his wall.
Look how cute she is
in the fuchsia.
I have been sent
by the spirit of Pete Rose.
Pete Rose isn't dead.
There was a photo of Pete Rose
on the wall.
Okay, why have I been drawn
here? Was there a murder?
Do I need the little booties
for the crime scene?
Thanks, but we're doing
just fine.
Don't go in the back room.
My grandpa
loved Pete Rose.
All right, I want you guys
ringing doorbells.
If anybody in the neighborhood saw
anything, I want to know about it.
Patient files. Cabinet's locked.
We haven't found the key.
Get ahold of the DA's office. Tell
him I need access to those files.
If they say we need
a warrant, get it.
Also, get me a copy
of his desk calendar.
I thought I told you no.
But your eyes said yes.
Hey, who's that Cincinnati Red
over there with the bowl cut?
Let me be perfectly clear.
This is my crime scene.
I don't need your help.
I don't want your help.
If you don't leave right now,
I will have you arrested
for interfering with
a police investigation.
Am I clear?
Like butter.
I've given this
a great deal of thought.
I think we should take
the rest of the day off.
What say you?
All we've done is eat up a box of
animal cookies and crash a crime scene.
The case with the doctor.
They're coming back to us
eventually. You know this.
So, let's go to the beach. It's too
nice a day for murder and mayhem.
I have
to see him right now. It's important.
I'm sorry. I don't mean to
barge in, but I need help.
Mr. Dunn, Robert, how can
we help? And can I call you Bob?
This is difficult.
Take your time. We're here.
Yeah.
I'm just gonna
come out and say it.
I'm being haunted.
Haunted?
Yes.
Haunting?
He's crazy.
Gus, can I talk
to you outside?
Not now, Shawn. We're in
the middle of something.
Gus.
Stop talking. Sit down.
Now, what exactly do you mean
when you say, haunted?
Well, my home,
sometimes I smell perfume
when no one else is around.
Things get broken or move.
Oh, Gus, I
think you have a text message.
I'll get it later. I think
you should get it now.
Sorry. Work business.
Okay.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah. Yeah.
Do these spirits ever
speak to you?
No. No. Whatever,
whoever it is,
it hasn't spoken to me.
Oh. Have you
contacted the police?
Yeah. But they said that there
was nothing they could do.
So, here I am.
Robert, we deal with this kind
of phenomenon all the time.
What you need to realize
is that evicting a spirit
is a very time-consuming and
absurdly expensive process.
I don't care, okay? I just
can't go on living this way.
Excuse me.
Oh, really?
Yes!
Yes, Shawn.
Look, all I'm saying is
that it might be easier
to try moving into a different
house, one that's less haunted.
I've tried that.
Whatever this thing is, it followed
me all the way from San Francisco.
Maybe it likes you.
No, I don't think so.
What makes you say that?
I think it tried to kill me.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Gus, what is all this?
Gear we might need.
If we're going to be hunting
spirits, we might as well do it right.
Methodically, systematically,
scientifically.
Who knows, we might be
surprised what we find.
Video camera? Nice. Audio
recorder, motion detectors.
Gus, I'm very impressed.
You only forgot one thing.
Really? What?
There's no such thing
as ghosts.
Yes, there is.
Oh, Gus, no.
Okay.
Stop.
Please. Let's just,
let's just stop.
Come here, sit down.
Please, sit.
All right, this is me
talking. This is Shawn.
What's going on? I usually to
have to drag you to these cases,
kicking and screaming, and
those are real police cases.
Now, all of a sudden we have
some client who's either bonkers
or, judging by the size
of the bags under his eyes,
suffering from nothing more than
waking dreams or hallucinations
and you, you're ready
to go ghost-hunting.
Talk to me.
All right.
I never told this to
anyone before, but I was 12.
Gus, it's me.
It was late.
I was in my room
with the lights off.
I heard a voice.
Gus, I'm sure there's a
perfectly logical explanation.
No, no, no, Shawn. It wasn't
on TV and it wasn't a radio.
It was coming from the walls.
And the voice,
the voice told me
that our house was built on
an old Indian burial ground.
Shut up.
And she said...
She said she was sad because
she had died many moons ago
and was trapped
between worlds.
When I asked her
her name, Shawn,
she said,
"My name..." "My name is Wilting Flower.
"I died without knowing love.
"Will you be my friend?"
How did you know that?
I never told that
to anyone before.
I was Wilting Flower.
Gus! I can't believe
that you fell for that.
I put an old walkie-talkie in the wall
when your dad put in the new insulation.
The old Indian burial ground,
you bought that?
I got that from Poltergeist
or Poltergeist II.
Gremlins?
No, it wasn't Gremlins.
That's not funny, Shawn.
You know what? Let's add
a "Trixie" to that.
She is the companion
to "Scrappy", right?
Okay, great. Let's add that
to Girl With Flowers
and Merry Musicians.
Okay, now listen, I need the
card to read, "Happy birthday.
"'Ex' is the loneliest letter
in the alphabet."
But I need you to spell it,
E-X, as in...
Oh, you got it.
Okay, well, see,
it continues,
"From your not yet 'ex',
E-X, husband,
"Carlton."
Perfect. These will
go out today, right?
All righty-dighty.
Thank you very much.
I didn't know
you collected figurines.
You know, I have a
grandmother... Do you not knock?
There's no door.
And?
Sorry. The DA's office called.
They said that we can have access
to Dr. Blinn's patients' files.
About time.
Let's go get in there,
get those addresses.
Bring these nut jobs
in for questioning.
Here's where I found all my
paintings last weekend upside down.
I've got
a cold spot. Right here.
Feel it?
Yes.
Yes, I do. Robert, we've
definitely got something here.
You're standing
under a vent.
So, all these are yours, huh?
Yeah. I'm trying to
get ready for a show.
No kidding. Has anything
strange ever happened here?
Sometimes I get the feeling that
the furniture has been moved.
Mmm-hmm.
Did you actually
see it happen?
No, no, I just come into a room and
everything's not where I left it.
Robert, do you have
a photo album?
Yeah.
Ah.
Hmm.
That's a nice shot, huh?
I feel it! I feel it.
Oh, Gus, Gus, oh!
Oh! She is angry!
She is angry! She is soaring!
With rage and...
She wants to go
to the bedroom!
Where's the bedroom?
It's here! Here!
Take me! Oh!
I've lost her.
You don't believe me,
do you?
No, no, of course we do.
You saw it, too, didn't you?
Guys,
please, stay the night.
Then you'll see.
I mean, you don't know
what it's been like.
I can't work.
I can't concentrate.
I wake up in the morning more
tired than when I went to bed.
Days pass when I can't
remember what I've done...
This pulls out into a bed,
but that's all I got.
Oh, no worries. What's a little
spooning between old pals, huh, Gus?
Well, good night.
Good night, Robert.
You got the floor.
Oh, we'll make it work.
You don't mind if I nude
up for the sleepover, right?
Seriously, Shawn, only one of us is sleeping
at a time. The other one is on watch.
Oh, no, we'll both sleep.
I'll put on some socks, make
you feel more comfortable.
Stop playing, Shawn.
We're here to solve a case.
I already solved it.
When? When you were flapping
a book like a bird?
Gus, if you must know,
it was a bald eagle.
And, yes.
You found the ghost?
There's no such thing
as ghosts.
Yes, there is, Shawn.
No, there isn't, but there is such
thing as a pissed off ex-girlfriend.
What ex-girlfriend?
No one mentioned
anything about an ex.
You didn't look
at the photo album?
Redhead. She's cute.
What makes you think
she's an ex?
Oh, come on, there's dirty
dishes everywhere.
His bedroom is a mess, his nails
are filthy, his hair is horrible.
No girlfriend is gonna
put up with that.
And, exhibit A,
who else would "X" through his
face in all these pictures?
Okay. Okay, say
she's the ex,
we still don't know
if she's actually been here.
There are strands of red hair
all over the studio.
Should we tell Robert?
How psychic would that be?
No, we'll spend the night.
It's fine.
Catch up with
the ex tomorrow.
Talk to her,
see what's going on.
Meanwhile, I'm going to do
some sit-ups.
Come hold my feet.
I'm going to do a thousand.
Shawn! Get up! Fire!
Get Robert!
I could have died.
If you guys weren't here, I...
Why is it doing this to me?
Why is it trying to kill me?
Okay. Okay, Robert,
hey, hey, hey.
Hey, Bobby, look at me.
Now, who here has communicated
with more dispossessed souls,
you or me?
You?
That's correct.
Now, I am telling you that this, this
fire was not an attempt on your life.
It wasn't?
No.
This was a sad
and desperate cry for help
from a very frightened,
very lonely apparition.
Are you sure about this?
Absolutely.
Of course it's also possible that
someone simply left a candle burning.
I don't burn candles.
Gus, did you burn
a candle?
Why would I do that?
Cry for help it is.
No one came in
while we were sleeping.
I checked the doors
and windows.
They were all locked
from the inside.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
That's all you did? Checked
the doors and the windows?
Yeah, why?
Where did that come from?
Don't look at me.
I'm not wearing lipstick.
This is the only post office
box listed for Regina Kane.
According to Dr. Blinn's calendar,
she was his last appointment.
She might have seen
something. I want to find her.
Well, if this is where she picks up
her mail, she probably lives close by.
Canvas the neighborhood,
see if anyone knows her.
That's a really
smart approach.
What? That,
that shocks you?
I meant that
as a compliment.
Really?
Yeah.
Thanks a lot.
Was that sarcastic?
No.
Oh.
Okay. You're welcome.
Do you still think
it's the ex-girlfriend?
A woman scorned
is a woman with motive.
We need to talk
to this woman.
You're on your own. I'm tied up
with work for the rest of the week.
Gus, that's so lame.
Pull over.
Good morning,
detectives.
Collecting donations
for the Policeman's Ball?
We don't have balls.
I honestly have
no response to that.
Need I remind you,
Mr. Spencer,
what happens when you interfere
with a police investigation?
The case gets solved?
Wait a minute, you guys are working
on that murder thingy, right?
I completely forgot
about that. How's that going?
Silly question. We'll let you guys
get back to your investigating.
Bye, Juliet.
Okay, where to next?
Listen, we change our clothes, we get some
lunch, then I have to get back to work.
Gus, the plot is thickening.
Shawn, I've already missed
two days this week.
Oh, fine, fine, fine.
I respect your wishes.
Thank you.
Jerk chicken.
You know that's right.
- Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
- There he is.
What time is it?
Daytime.
What happened?
I might have dropped six allergy pills
in your frosty while you were peeing.
You did what?
Where are we?
Palo Alto.
San Francisco?
No, but close.
Robert's ex-girlfriend lives up here,
Gus, and we really need to talk to her.
I will kill you, Shawn.
And then you're going to
buy me some new tires.
Oh, come on. This is fun.
Road trip.
Kidnapping.
That's exactly what this is.
That's it. We're not talking.
What, seriously?
So, we're really
not talking now?
Come on,
how mature is this?
The silent treatment is not how
conflict gets resolved, Gus.
We need to work through this,
we need to share our feelings,
maybe a smoothie.
Yes?
Never mind.
It's not her.
Pardon me.
What do I mean,
"It's not her?"
Lips. The lips don't match.
The lips that kissed your forehead
do not belong to Amy Kessler.
Therefore,
she's not our ghost.
"You didn't drive all the way out here so
you could say, 'It's not her' and leave.
"We're talking to hep."
"Her."
"Carlton,
"separation means apart."
What you got there?
Nothing.
Are you okay?
Of course I'm okay.
You look sad.
I am sad.
Why are you sad?
I'm sad because I don't have my
forensics report on my dead doctor.
Or a lead on my possible
witness, Regina Kane.
What about that psychic guy?
Isn't Shawn great
at this sort of thing?
Finding people. I mean,
maybe we should bring him...
Maybe you should just
keep your ideas to yourself.
That's a joke, right?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Okay.
Very nice.
Exquisite brush strokes.
It's a print.
I'm referring, of course,
to the original.
I'm sorry, what's the name
of your gallery again?
That's been a bit
of a problem, actually.
We wanted to call it
Le Petit Louvre,
but apparently
the art snobs in France
think they have a monopoly
on all things Louvre.
We also tried
Louvre Two,
Louvre, Junior,
Night Gallery,
nothing cleared.
The important thing is we want to
show the amazing work of Robert Dunn
and he listed you
as a character reference.
Oh, we are very select with the clients
that we take on, isn't that right, Francois?
I have to admit, I'm surprised Robert
would list me as a character reference.
We dated for a period
and it didn't end well.
Can I ask why?
Not to pry, but he did
list you as a reference.
The usual, forgetting dates,
standing me up,
sometimes he'd get so wrapped up in his
work he'd disappear for days at a time.
The worst was when he cheated
on me and lied about it.
Oh. You must have been
burning with furious anger.
He was just so stupid.
A girlfriend of mine saw him
at a club with another woman.
He was drunk and pretended that she
had him confused with someone else.
He said his name was,
get this, Martin Brody.
Martin Brody?
Roy Scheider's character
from Jaws?
Yes. How did you know?
I've seen Jaws.
It's his favorite movie. Anyway,
when I asked him about it,
he pretended he'd never
even heard of the club.
That's... horrible.
You must have
wanted to kill him.
Probably not
so much anymore.
You're pretty happily
engaged, aren't you?
Yes. Isn't the ring great?
Okay, so
she's not our ghost.
Even the longest journeys
can start with a tiny misstep.
Overall, still
a very good day.
How is it a good day?
Oh, come on, Gus.
First of all, road trip,
always fun.
We got some fresh-baked
sourdough, very nice.
And the agency is sending us
a new secretary tomorrow.
And yes, she speaks
English fluently.
Shawn, we talked about this.
We can't afford a receptionist.
I don't think we can afford
not to have one.
Gus?
What?
I think maybe we should move.
Come on, Gus! Get it in gear!
Go! Go! Go!
Hey! Hey!
Guy's like a Whippet.
Tell me about it.
What's the supersmeller say?
Somebody had
too much to drink.
What are you so happy for?
We almost got killed.
This was not an accident.
Whoever that is was waiting for us and
we have a new suspect for Robert's ghost.
He didn't answer his phone.
Maybe he's not home.
Robert?
Or maybe whoever tried to kill us
last night also paid Robert a visit.
And left the door unlocked.
Anybody home?
Robert?
Bob?
Shawn, you might
want to see this.
"Save me. I'm trapped."
Hmm.
I don't want to jump
to conclusions here,
but this very well
may be a cry for help.
Maybe someone died here.
Or was buried alive.
This could be the cry
of a tortured soul.
So this guy just happens to move
into two haunted houses in a row?
Don't touch that.
It's blood.
It's not blood.
Enjoy your hepatitis.
And this tortured soul might be
less tortured with a latex enamel.
He wouldn't get
these messy drips.
Now what?
I got it.
I got it. I got it.
Hallelujah.
Wow.
What?
You got to see this.
Huh.
Not what I was expecting.
Okay, I know what I'm looking
at, but what does it mean?
Is it a ghost?
No, buddy, it's not a ghost.
Is there a woman
living up here?
Well, that would certainly explain
the perfume Robert's been smelling
and all the red hair laying
everywhere, but no, no dice.
Then, what is it?
Oh, come on, Gus. Look.
What?
Robert is a woman.
No, he's not.
Not all the time,
but sometimes.
No. Doesn't seem
like the type.
He's not the type.
Then how?
Unless he has that
personality thing.
What personality thing?
Oh, you know
what I'm talking about.
The multiple
personality disease.
You know, that
what's her name had,
The Flying Nun in the
other thing, the TV movie.
Smokey and the Bandit?
Yeah, dude, Smokey
and the Bandit. Yes.
What does that have to do
with multiple personalities?
You asked.
I asked a real question.
You were supposed to give me a
real answer, not a random guess.
Okay. Fine. Hooper.
Hooper?
Hooper.
Hooper was a stuntman.
Oh.
I don't think Sally Field is even
in Hooper. Who are you thinking of?
Oh...
Terry Bradshaw.
Yes.
Is it Norma Rae?
No, but that would have
made that movie a lot cooler.
The thing you asked
about Shawn,
is referred to as
dissociative identity disorder.
That's it! That's what Robert
has, Gus. It all makes sense.
Do you know
how rare that is?
I'm not saying all of Santa Barbara
has it, just Robert. One guy.
I think that qualifies
as pretty rare.
I don't know, Shawn.
These are huge.
Look. Think about it.
There's two separate,
but distinct personalities,
one body.
One's a man,
the other's a woman.
The female personality
cooks dinner.
Robert thinks the meals
are the work of a ghost.
The female rearranges
the furniture.
Robert thinks the ghost is moving
things when he's not around.
His old girlfriend did say that he
would disappear for stretches at a time,
which would explain when the
female personality was in control,
Robert would disappear.
And he would have
no clue to any of it.
Now, all we need to figure out is how to bring
out the woman so that we can talk to her.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Triggers.
We shoot him? Then what?
No, no, sights,
sounds, smells.
Something that would trigger
the personality to come out.
Triggers it is.
Gus, this is going to be
kind of cool.
Or weird.
Where did all this stuff
come from?
Is this
where she lives?
The angry female spirit
that you sensed?
Oh, yes.
I feel her very
strongly here, Robert.
Do you?
Do you feel
pretty?
What?
Do you feel pretty?
He means
do you feel a...
female presence?
No, but I'm not a psychic.
Do you think that you can
Communicate with her?
I'm trying. I am.
Sorry.
Okay. You guys are
starting to creep me out.
So, if I'm not needed, I
think I'll go back downstairs.
Okay. Let me just put this away.
We'll all go down together.
You coming, Shawn?
Yes.
Oh, wow, Robert,
these are some
terrific clothes.
I bet they look absolutely
beautiful on you,
Regina.
Regina? Who...
Who are you talking to?
Yes. Yes, Gus,
why don't you tell Regina
how much you like
her nice clothes.
Wow.
Yeah, Regina.
Regina.
You look beautiful.
Regina?
Thank you, Gus.
I can't tell you
how glad I am
that you got my message.
So,
do you think that
you can help me?
Please.
Dude.
This isn't right.
I must look horrible.
No. Not at all.
You are too kind.
But then again, I already knew
that the way you comforted Robert.
You are so sweet.
Unlike most men,
afraid to show their emotions.
I've been hurt a lot.
Now if you two don't mind,
I really must put on my face.
Wow.
So, Regina, this message
on the wall,
this was your way of trying
to get Robert's attention?
Well, he doesn't even know
I'm alive.
Why not write him a letter? Or
an e-mail? Even a post-it even?
I tried. I really did try.
But every time, something
or someone stopped you.
What are you talking about? I
think there's another personality.
Regina, there's another
personality, isn't there?
I mean, you don't smash
pictures or start fires.
You would never
strangle Robert.
No, I wouldn't.
Regina, the police would
like to speak with you.
They're investigating
Dr. Blinn's murder.
They think you might have seen
something. You could be in danger.
I didn't see anything.
I didn't even go
to my appointment.
Why would anyone
want to hurt Dr. Blinn?
He was such a nice man and he
was doing so much to help me.
With what?
Well, you ought to know
better than to ask that.
That's between a woman
and her doctor.
Okay.
Unless you're going to ask her
out, I think we're done here.
How do we get Robert back?
I have no idea.
Well, you're her
very special friend.
Regina?
We would like to
speak with Robert.
Can you let Robert
come out and play?
For you,
of course I can.
Thank you.
And I do hope
that we meet again.
Robert.
Robert?
Try Bob.
Easy, easy,
easy, easy.
We know it seems weird
and... Actually, it is.
Yeah.
It's really weird.
But we have good news.
We figured out
who your ghost is.
Who?
You.
You're haunting
yourself.
Yep. Life is good.
Life is great.
I mean, Robert gets the help
he so desperately needs,
we get to marinate in the delicious
satisfaction of another job well done.
And leading Lassiter to Regina,
even though she saw nothing.
That's professional courtesy.
Plus it helps
raise our stock, Gus.
Crime scene photos.
Love crime scene photos.
May I help you?
Detective O'Hara,
what a truly pleasant
surprise. Mmm-hmm.
I just dropped by to tell
Detective Lassiter that I have...
We have information regarding the
whereabouts of a one, Regina Kane.
How did you know about it?
Never mind. Stay right here.
Don't move. I'll go find him.
Ooh.
Shawn.
Shawn, don't do this.
Look at this. Look at this.
Look! Look! Look!
Here, on the floor where poor
Dr. Blinn's body was laying.
A toothpick.
A chewed toothpick.
Yeah? So?
Don't you remember?
The car that tried
to ram us, on the seat?
Chewed toothpick. Oh!
Oh! That means the person
that killed Dr. Blinn
is the same person
that tried to kill us.
It's a chewed
toothpick, Shawn.
Lots of people
chew toothpicks.
Yes, but we were working for Robert. Robert
is also Regina. Regina is a patient of...
Dr. Blinn.
Yes! Take the baton!
So, whoever the killer is
knew both Robert and Regina.
He said his name was, get this,
Martin Brody. How dumb is that?
Oh! Martin Brody.
Of course! That's Robert's other
personality. The violent one.
But, why would he kill
Dr. Blinn?
Depends entirely on what
Regina was seeing him for.
Oh, you've got
to be kidding me.
What?
Dr. Blinn's patient files.
All we have to do
is find Regina's.
What are you doing?
Hmm?
Shooting. It relaxes me.
Shawn Spencer says he has
information for you.
Where is he?
At your desk.
Is anyone watching him?
Found it!
Oh, no.
What?
Gender reassignment?
Oh, Regina started feeling like
a woman trapped in a man's body,
so she wants
to have her parts...
Oh, my...
Wait a second.
That means
if Regina was successful,
both Robert and the Martin personality
would also lose their parts.
Martin can't do
anything to hurt Regina
because he would
only be hurting himself.
So, dressed as Regina,
he goes after Dr. Blinn.
That would explain how
Robert got the marks on his neck.
And with Dr. Blinn dead,
Robert figured that Regina would change
her mind about the gender reassignment.
Right.
We got that, Shawn!
Only she hasn't.
Gus, no, no, she found another
doctor. She's seeing him today.
When?
Right now.
Right now, Shawn?
Like, in 10 minutes.
Oh, okay.
There had better be a really
good explanation for this.
He was in some sort of trance.
I couldn't control him.
He says this is the killer.
The killer,
he's going to kill again.
This is ridiculous.
Who? Who's he going to kill?
What is it, Shawn?
Watch out! Watch out!
Oh!
Dr. Drake?
Gender reassignment?
That's a big step, Regina.
Why don't you tell me
why it's important to you?
It's okay. The machine can
get that. This is your time.
Thank you, Dr. Drake.
No answer. Just the machine.
We have to go now.
It could already be too late.
Let's go!
I know this can be
a difficult process,
but it really is necessary
to ensure that you're ready
psychologically
for a change like this.
You do seem like an excellent
candidate for the surgery.
Our time is up.
Why don't we pick up here
again next week? Okay, Regina?
Okey-dokey.
Only
my name is not Regina.
Hold it!
Get up!
- What's going on?
- Robert?
Bob? You back there, buddy?
What am I doing here?
Great. Thanks.
Good news.
They're going to admit Robert into
the HT Windsor Facility in Chicago.
And his doctor thinks
his prognosis is good.
Don't you understand, Shawn?
That's the premier mental
health hospital in the country.
That's good. That's awesome.
Who is that?
Leslie.
Oh. Oh. No, no, no, no.
Leslie's supposed to be
a swimsuit model.
Unfortunately, he is. Although, he says
he's getting completely sick of the grind.
I have to call the agency.
They're completely
misrepresenting their clientele.
Leslie's a guy's name, too.
Okay.
We have to fire him.
Fire him? On what grounds?
What grounds? On the
grounds that he's a dude.
That's discrimination.
We can't do that.
Okay, listen to me.
No woman is going to
look at us twice
if we're sharing our office
with that ridiculous Adonis.
He's better looking
than both of us put together.
Yeah.
I'm not doing that.
But, Gus,
you know I can't fire people.
They look too sad.
This was your idea.
Figure it out.
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know