Excuse me,
you're in my seat.
Am I?
Actually, yes, you are.
You one of those
weirdo compulsives
who come to the same restaurant,
sit in the same chair,
and eat the same food
every day?
No, no, no, I was sitting
right there three minutes ago,
and then I went outside
to get myself a paper.
I ordered a juice, and look, I made a
crawling snake with the straw wrapper.
You can finish it if you think
you're up to the job.
I'm sorry.
You want me to move?
Not anymore.
So, what's up? I don't
have time to talk.
But you haven't heard
what I'm going to say.
See, now we've already
talked more than I wanted to.
Well, I did give you
my seat, you know.
I think that gets me
one question.
Listen, diner guy...
Shawn.
Shawn. Flattered, really.
Very often, I am happy
to meet new people.
But today, right here,
right now, I can't talk.
I understand. I do.
What if I do the talking
for both of us?
Have at it!
Do you mind if
I read the paper
and stare aimlessly out the
window while you two talk?
No. Can I get a name
to work with?
Juliet.
Well, it's very nice
to meet you, Juliet.
It's
nice to meet you, too, Shawn.
And I am sorry about your
seat. So, lunch is on me.
So, what do you
do for a living?
I do a
little bit of everything.
Oh, that sounds interesting.
And maybe a little bit
dangerous.
Oh, I like your jacket.
I like it...
Okay, can I stop you here?
First off, in your
portrayal of me,
I sound like I'm
in the eighth grade.
Well, in my portrayal of you, you
only have an eighth grade education.
All right, smarten you up.
College, yeah?
Top your class,
graduate early... Got it.
I'm new to
town, and I don't know many people.
But I do know my cats.
Two of them.
The gray one is
very affectionate,
the white one makes me work much,
much harder for the attention.
And what about your family?
My family is amazing!
My parents have been together
for, what is it, 30 years now?
Okay, do we know each other?
Yes, you were the girl
who stole my seat!
Oh, my gosh, you're a cop!
I'm not a cop!
The paper, the vantage point,
the layout, of course!
You got defensive when Scary Guy
walked in, you're totally a cop!
Okay, Shawn, I may need you
to do me a favor.
Name it.
Duck!
Police!
Gun! Go!
Let me go!
Get him up!
Come on!
First time
pulling your gun?
Maybe.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Thirty seconds,
Mr. Guster.
A-G...
...G...
Let me start over!
"Aggiornamento."
A...
...G...
...O...
Beautiful
Santa Barbara, California,
is the backdrop for this afternoon's
coverage of the American Spelling Bee,
being held at the downtown
Cabrillo Theater.
Champions from all over
these western United States
have made the trek to test...
What are you watching?
Nothing.
Is that Korean porn?
Come on, man!
It's the Regional Finals
of the American Spelling Bee.
What?
Don't mock me.
It's a huge event.
No, I'm just... I'm shocked that
you didn't take the whole day off.
It's on Sports Cal Two,
for your information.
And it's hosted
by Bud Collins.
Really? Did they bump the car
washing championships for this?
And is it over soon? 'Cause I'd like
to get back to the woodcarving finals.
Let's recap this
morning's unexpected high drama.
It's being held in
Santa Barbara this year.
Down at the Cabrillo.
It's huge. Sold out.
All the experts are
shaking their heads.
I tried to get tickets,
but you gotta know somebody.
Somebody lame. Dude, I can't
believe you're watching that!
I'm taping it! And I don't
care what you think, Shawn,
I watch the bee semis
every year.
Okay, for your sake and mine, stop giving
the spelling bee hip little nicknames.
For those
of you who have just joined us,
well, a bit of a shock.
And a little sad, too.
The heavy favorite has had a
bad spell, and Brendan Vu is out!
What?
Boo-hoo for Vu, Bud.
No way. Brendan Vu is out?
Already?
Okay, now you're
just scaring me.
Come on, Shawn. He took second
last year, everybody knows that!
No, Gus, nobody knows that,
except for Brendan and his mother.
Okay.
We're gonna show this again.
It looks like
young Mr. Vu
may be having
trouble breathing.
He does look to be under
some sort of duress, Bud.
His inhaler did not appear
to help, and Vu tumbled.
Dang! Paramedics
rushed to the scene,
and within moments, the competition
had taken an unexpected turn.
Wait a second.
Did you see that?
This is no accident. There's
something wrong with that inhaler.
Shawn, get out of here.
For 35 minutes,
competition was suspended.
Psych.
...and Vu and his family were
rushed to the hospital. It's the Chief.
I'll have to check with Gus.
Are we available?
Appears we are.
We'll be right there.
What? I can get us
into the spelling bee.
Really?
Guess I was right about
the whole Bandon Dunes thing.
Brendan Vu.
Sure.
They need a psychic
detective for that?
They don't,
unless he was sabotaged.
The kid said his
inhaler felt funny.
When he used it,
his hand stung,
paramedics get there,
there's no inhaler.
Apparently, the thing just
vanished into thin air.
Shawn, we are so taking this!
Let's go!
How come I can't get you this
excited about girls? Let's go, Shawn!
Or Mexico?
We're here!
Go on in, Mr. Spencer. I've
arranged everything you need inside.
You're leaving? Oh, I was only
here for the mayor's presentation,
and we have a robbery
standoff across town.
Whoa, shouldn't I go
to the hospital,
meet the victim,
get his statement?
Mr. Spencer,
the case is sabotage.
There are 43 remaining contestants,
all presumably with a motive.
Now, you can read guilt just
by talking with someone, right?
Do it.
You want us to talk to all
of them? And their parents.
Today?
Mmm-hmm. By 5:00.
In two days,
this whole thing is over.
At that time, all the witnesses
will be in 100 different cities
all over the western
United States.
So, it's now or never.
Good luck.
Spellmaster Elvin
Cavanaugh is a secretive guy,
and yet, he has called for a
press conference after this round!
Can you repeat that, please?
"Butyraceous."
Definition, please?
Adjective.
"Having the characteristics
of butter. "
This thing's been
sold out for weeks.
I can see why. It moves so fast,
it's like hockey with words.
There's Elvin Cavanaugh, the
greatest spell champion ever.
He's been the spellmaster
for 14 years.
He's a legend.
Wow.
"Butyraceous."
He sits up there all by
himself in that fancy box?
Language of origin?
What is he, the
Phantom of the Opera?
He's a huge celebrity! He
can't just sit in the crowd!
Can you repeat the word?
"Butyraceous."
"Butyraceous"?
Oh, come on, dude,
you're not bored at all?
Do you know how to spell
any of these words?
Proudly. I have never heard
of any of these words.
I file these words under
"Things to say
"when I want to be ridiculed
or kicked out of bed."
See, the problem is that butyraceous
is clearly a Round One word.
Oh, God, stop talking.
I'd like to pretend we still
have things in common, Gus!
Well, instead of sitting here,
maybe we should get to work!
Try not to break anything.
Wow!
So this is what
it looks like.
What?
The comfort room.
This is where you go to
deal with missing a word.
Oh, yeah? Where do they
take you to deal with
missing your entire
childhood?
Shawn, this misplaced malevolence
you have with the spelling bee
is getting monotonous.
Stop hating on the bee!
I'm sorry, ma'am, I do apologize
for his inappropriate virulence.
Why are you using all these
big-ass words all of a sudden?
I'm not doing that.
That's preposterous!
I was in the spelling bee
myself.
I almost won.
Dude, are you
still on that?
Of course I'm still on it!
I know it wasn't "O"!
You may have five minutes
with each contestant, no more.
If the room is needed,
you'll be asked to vacate.
I'll begin with the
eliminated contestants.
Actually, we'd only like
to speak with the ones
that were still in the competition
when the accident occurred.
Ms. Foote.
And let's start with the
shifty-eyed ones, shall we?
And you were there
the whole time?
I was.
Assimilation.
A-S-S-l-M-l-L-A-T-l-O-N.
My son, no one expect him
to come this far.
But he surprise everyone.
You watch him win.
Oh, I don't know. Are they
running odds on this thing now?
'Cause I've got some cash
I'd like to lay down
on the really, really tall
girl with the bulldog underbite.
What, is she on stilts?
You do not understand.
This contest, it is
money for scholarship.
It is entry into any
school in the future.
Yeah, Shawn.
The winner of this competition can
just about choose his university.
Your friend is right.
And it teaches
grace under pressure.
Poise. Dignity.
All things you can get at a
hot-dog eating competition.
Plus...
Hot dogs.
Still studying, huh?
Oh, she loves it.
Won't put that thing down.
Well, kudos on
the childrearing.
Let me know how
the therapy goes.
Huh?
We're gonna keep rolling because of the
exceptional request by Elvin Cavanaugh,
a behind-the-scenes guy,
to give a press conference
right here at this stage
of the competition!
What's that all about?
Well, I mean, this could
be something big, Bud.
I mean, this year's competition has
just been peppered with controversy.
It certainly has.
Well, he's been watching from a
private box on the balcony, but now,
he's going to come out
so that we can see him.
This could
be something big, Bud.
I think he's having
difficulty breathing!
He does look
under duress, Bud.
Oh, jeez!
Oh, my! Oh, my God! Oh!
- Call 911!
- Okay, move over.
Okay. Not to belittle
this guy's life,
but this just got more interesting
than the woodcarving finals.
When do we decide if we
should cancel this event?
Why would we cancel?
Well, a body did just
tumble into the crowd.
Didn't land on anybody.
It might be traumatic.
For who?
The mayor, when he realizes all
the hotel rooms are now empty?
We could postpone at least a
day, I'm sure that's allowed.
Do you have any idea how important
this event is to the city?
Now, unhealthy guy
has heart attack,
falls over railing.
Case closed.
Certainly not declaring it
a crime scene.
Come on, you can
introduce me to the press.
Okay, just be sensitive.
How about if we don't sell
the seat the guy landed on?
Can I help you?
Has anyone come
out of there?
Just the cops. I've
been here the whole time.
Did you hear anything
from in there?
I'm sorry, who are you?
I'm Shawn Spencer, I'm a psychic
with the police department.
I'm sorry, Mr. Spencer. Look,
I don't doubt your ability,
I actually have an aunt who can see
apparitions, and some spooky stuff.
But they told me not to let anybody
in here without a badge, so...
I see.
Okay. As long as
you feel safe.
Safe?
What with the dead guy's spirit
being here, and him being so angry.
How angry?
Well, considering he might
have just been murdered,
that's definitely
a negative.
Man, I wouldn't be happy!
No, please, spare me!
I'm here to help you! Gus!
Back me up here!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Segrete ammunus!
You guys just take
a quick little look-see, okay?
I'll be downstairs!
Come on, get up!
Well, we certainly know
what his vice was.
He was a heavy eater,
so what?
Nothing. I'm just thinking
Lassiter's heart attack theory
might not be so far off.
Who's Contestant 1953?
It only goes up
to 200-something.
What's 1953 mean?
Nothing.
Is it a rule? No, they don't
really number the rules like that.
Think there was
an altercation?
No, something else. He was
all by himself up here.
You smell that?
Dude, don't look at me.
It's sulfuric.
Gus, I am not the one
who had the egg salad.
No, no, no. We manufactured
something last year, heavy stuff.
When it starts to go bad,
smelled the same.
You could pick out a bottle
across the warehouse.
I can't smell anything!
Well, you don't have
the supersmeller.
Gus! You have got to stop calling
your nose the supersmeller.
You wanna nickname
a body part?
Nickname your butt, man!
Call it the "tightbouncer,"
or the "hexagon."
Ladies are gonna dig that,
I'm telling you.
It's there. It's right there.
It's subtle, but it's right there.
Well, what is it?
I don't know.
It's nothing we manufacture.
Aren't you supposed to
know this kind of stuff?
Shawn, I sell pharmaceutical
supplies, I'm not a scientist!
But you're saying it is
something? Yes, I'm pretty sure.
Don't eat it!
What, do I look
like an idiot?
What... What... Are you
taking some to go?
Yes! For the road! In case
later on I get hungry enough
to eat something
that might be poisoned!
There are four up there,
and two on the other side.
What, you mean those
two guys up there?
Excuse me, hi, it's time.
The press are ready.
Thank you.
All right.
Man, we gotta go!
Sorry, could I just
try that again?
I kind of fumbled
the "safe and secure" part.
Sure.
Be sensitive.
Of course.
The finals will continue
tomorrow as scheduled.
At this point, all indications are Mr.
Cavanaugh was having a heart attack,
stumbled forward, falling
over the railing to his death.
But we wanna
assure everyone
that this building
is both safe and...
Our sympathies go out
to Mr. Cavanaugh's family,
and we would like
to offer counseling
- to anyone who feels that they might need it.
- Who's the blonde?
Lassiter's new partner. They
transferred his girlfriend.
And again, we wanna ensure everyone
coming out for this fantastic event
that it is entirely safe.
Shawn! They're gonna
stop investigating!
One last question, and then I
really have to go wrap up this thing.
Do something!
Is there any word as to what
Cavanaugh's big announcement was?
Moo goo gai pan!
Beef lo mein, kung pao!
Check the food!
It was murder!
Oh, did I just say
all that out loud?
Shawn, you'll never find out
what that is without a lab.
I'll get a lab.
A high-tech lab?
Right now?
Maybe.
Might have
a connection.
Yo!
Shawn.
Hey, Dad, great shirt!
You want something.
Why do you always think
I want something?
Oh, you don't want anything.
What a pleasant surprise.
Okay, you got me!
I want something.
I got a poker game
in 45 minutes.
You still talk
to Jim Syklan?
Syklan? Sometimes.
Why, what's he to you?
Is he still working at the
regional crime lab out here?
Last I checked. Why?
I need to know
what this is.
It looks like a Number 15
with chicken.
Dad, you made a joke!
I think
there's poison in it.
Goodbye, Shawn.
It's just one time! Once!
No cases, Shawn! I was
painfully clear about that.
Oh, no, no,
this isn't for a case.
This is for a friend.
Oh, friend, different.
No!
Look, I'll do anything, whatever
you want, it's one favor.
Anything he can tell me about this
would be very helpful, it's serious.
Shawn, this is really
important to you?
Extremely.
And you'll do anything?
Name it.
Grab a saw.
What, now?
Well, you said you'd
do anything, right?
You know, most people will wait five, six
whole minutes before they cash in a favor.
I will not saw through
bone for you.
The doghouse?
From eighth grade?
Well, it's not really
a doghouse.
Not yet.
What do you
want me to do?
Finish it.
What, now?
Or whenever you want
your information.
You got more wood out back, nails on the
workbench, Home Depot's open till 9:00.
Don't cut any corners.
You're insane!
You're losing light.
Make sure you lock up.
It's creepy that
you kept this!
Shawn, you've
done absolutely nothing
to convince me that you're
responsible enough for a dog.
You'll never give me
a chance.
Chances are earned, Shawn.
You'll never
let me earn it!
Fair enough.
You're gonna need
a doghouse.
I saw one at the hardware
store. No. No, no, no.
You're gonna make it.
I can't.
Well, it seems to me
that somebody who thinks
they're responsible enough
for the life of an animal
should certainly be able to construct
a roof for the ratty little thing.
All right, I'll make it.
I'll make it right now.
What is that?
"What is that?" It's the
doghouse. No, it's not.
What are you talking about?
I gave you specifications.
When?
When I gave you the job.
In 1989?
Shawn, you know as well as I
do this is not what I asked for.
Keep working.
Don't be too loud.
The neighbors are
trying to sleep.
You expect me to
be okay with this?
I worked hard on it.
Shawn, you've been at this
for hours now.
The nails aren't
pounded in all the way,
the base has gotta be
up off the ground.
If it rains, the rain's
gonna flow right in.
And who's gonna fit in
through that door?
That door's not high enough.
I built it, Dad,
what do you want me to do?
I want you to do it right.
Listen, Dr. Sloane, if I can get
you this product this afternoon,
would it be possible to sit
down with you to discuss the...
M- A...
The unbelievable results
we've been having...
...O...
I'm sorry.
Can I call you back?
Thanks.
Burton Guster. Shawn?
You're in the hospital?
What happened?
You call your dad?
I'm fine.
They're releasing me.
Did you call him?
Gus, I am not gonna
talk to my dad.
He'd wanna know
you're okay.
All he cares about
are results.
Just like those possessed
spelling bee parents.
You know what's wrong
with this? All of this.
Shawn, you're delirious.
You're upset.
You lost control of
your bike last night.
Gus, I didn't lose
control of anything.
Someone tried to kill me or
send a very serious message.
Brendan appreciates you
checking on him.
Well, we were in
the neighborhood.
And, Gus here
is a huge fan.
He almost won the
spelling bee himself.
I took some bad advice.
Well, Brendan's
going home tomorrow.
He's fine.
He's more upset about
missing the spelling bee.
Well, maybe they'll decide
to redo the whole thing.
Why'd they do that?
Did you see the inhaler?
Same one as that
little Czech kid?
Get me a seating chart.
I'll bet you I know who Brendan
was sitting next to on day one.
I already checked it out.
Nice!
Shawn, something's going
on with that Czech kid.
Talk to me. The doctor on his
inhaler, Dr. Zavin, in Ventura?
Yeah?
He doesn't exist.
I do training on that route. The
last doctor in the book is Youngerman.
I double-checked it today.
You're saying that inhaler...
Is a fake.
Where you going?
I am going to build
a doghouse!
I thought you gave up.
Yeah, well, it doesn't
appear so, huh?
What happened to your leg?
Absolutely nothing.
You're running your roofing
vertical there, huh?
Yeah.
You might wanna pop
a ridge beam in first.
Well, yeah, that's a given.
What the hell
are you doing?
I'm gonna help you.
You've never helped me
before, ever.
You've never asked.
Put a nail in here.
All right. This is weird.
No, thanks.
Not bad.
"Not bad"?
It's like the Park Hyatt
for poodles.
Will you call Jack Syklan?
What is this?
Your results.
We had an agreement.
This is a derivative of methyl
parathion. High-grade stuff.
Whatever you're into,
I want you to get out quick.
I'm not kidding.
Wait a sec. How did you
get this so quickly?
Hmm? Oh, Syklan's a part
of my poker game.
So you didn't even
have to call him?
That game was at his house.
And I did all of that
for nothing?
For nothing? Shawn, you've never
completed a thing in your life.
Now you have.
Poisoned?
I feel somebody
poisoned his food.
There is a
Styrofoam container, yes,
and a...
"Happiness is a golden poem."
What?
A fortune cookie!
This is ridiculous.
Is it?
Mr. Spencer, what we have now points
to a medical condition, not murder.
All appearances show Mr. Cavanaugh
having an anaphylactic reaction.
Not to be out of line, but that could
be triggered by several types of poisons.
Or altered medications.
Or shellfish, which
he was allergic to.
Those results will show up
in the toxicology report,
which we will have a copy of
in approximately two weeks.
No, no, no!
That'll be too late.
All the contestants
will be gone...
Home.
You won't be able to finish
a real investigation.
Chief, I sense this!
Look, something
got out of control
and the perpetrator was
willing to kill to cover it up!
What proof do you have?
Only what I feel.
Why are you still
listening to this crap?
Dude, what is your glitch?
You! You're my glitch!
Look, he got nowhere with his
little inhaler assignment,
and then he tells the media
that we had a murder scene!
Cut him loose, Karen!
I mean, do whatever you
think is best, Chief.
Mr. Cavanaugh was gonna make an
announcement. What about that?
The Director said he'd
recently spoken of retiring.
That's not what
he was gonna say.
Oh, you know?
I know.
Mr. Spencer, I asked you to check
in about the inhaler incident.
If you or your partner
have anything about that,
I'd be happy
to hear about it.
Otherwise...
We gotta get back into
the spellmaster's room.
Are you serious?
Gus, the killer was there!
There's gotta be some other
piece of evidence inside.
We're not gonna have
time to get in there.
Besides, it's locked.
We'll make it work.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
How hard is it to get into
this event without a ticket?
Impossible.
The new spellmaster.
Check it out.
It's exactly what
I was hoping you'd say.
You can't do
that to him!
Gus, he has to learn sometime
that smoking is bad for him.
We're picking it up
as a new round commences.
A lot of excitement
in the air. Ooh, yeah.
The tension is becoming
butyraceous, Bud.
I'm so sorry if my agonizing
pain is inconveniencing you.
What's this?
It's a mark on a carpet.
Let's go.
Someone must have
heard that.
Thirty seconds. Live
to air. Positions, please.
Time's up, Shawn.
Did you hear me, Shawn?
I've got something!
Yes!
Ten seconds.
Prepare the next word.
That can't be right.
It doesn't mean anything,
Shawn, let's go.
Broadcast in five,
four, three, two...
Maybe this direction.
Hello? We need the word now.
Is everything okay?
Leann, something's wrong,
send security.
No, sorry for the delay.
Give me a word!
A word?
Yeah! Something hard,
but something you can spell.
I can spell anything.
Except "aggiornamento."
Give me one!
No!
You are not gonna
be spellmaster!
Gus, give me a word so we can
get out of here! We're so close!
Is everything okay up there?
It's fine.
"Banana."
Can you repeat that?
Yes.
"Banana."
"Banana," Shawn?
This is the third round!
You could have helped me!
This is a dead end, Shawn,
we're walking. Let's go!
Definition, please?
What?
A yellow fruit.
Also, a kind of pudding.
A delicious pudding.
Sentence, please?
"Anna Banana would like
to hear Venus by Bananarama. "
"Banana."
B- A-N-A-N-A. Banana.
Oh, wait a second,
I've got something!
Dude, we got him!
He was watching the Czech.
Let me see.
We need to get
the next word.
Give me a word.
No!
You're ruining
the whole event!
Suit yourself.
"Onion."
"Onion?"
Even Dan Quayle
could spell that.
O- N-l-O-N. Onion.
Are we off the list, Bill?
No, everything's fine.
You're using
his grocery list!
You refused to help me!
Now I gotta give them
something else.
"Mitchum."
"Mitchum"?
Yes.
"When I go to Albertsons, I need
to buy some Mitchum Ice Blast. "
"And bananas."
That wasn't me!
I was locked outside.
I have a reputation
to uphold!
So he was watching the Czech,
we have no proof.
There was no film
in the camera!
He was using that lens for something
else besides taking pictures. Now, what?
Cavanaugh was known for
ferreting out rule breakers.
He once caught a kid stealing
the advance word list.
And everything he did
had a purpose.
You couldn't have grabbed
one of these five minute ago?
We're down to
the final two spellers.
This has been a hard-fought
battle right from the start!
We've had tragedy,
controversy,
but when it really mattered, these
kids put together a fantastic display
of the power of learning.
Look at this. Brendan Vu
went down on "gladiolus."
So?
So? If I'd been able to see any of
the competition, I could have told you
that was the winning word from
the first spelling bee in 1929.
Okay, you're
scaring me again.
All of these words from that
round were the winning words.
They do that once in a while,
they make it a theme round.
This one won the 1985 bee,
this one from 1943.
Gus, what are
you saying?
Guess which kid got
the winning word from 1953?
You're staring at his father.
Gus, that's who Cavanaugh
was gonna disqualify.
That's what he was
tracking in the rulebook!
1953! It was 1953.
Jiri Prochazka,
you have the next word.
"Mastoparietal."
Part of speech?
It is an adjective.
Could I
have the definition?
Yes.
"Relating to the mastoid
portion of the temporal bone,
"and to the parietal lobe."
M...
...A-S-T...
...O-P-A-R-I...
I got him.
Let's call the Chief.
And this year's winner of the
Central California Regionals
is Jiri Prochazka!
Move out, people, this is what
you came to see, right here.
This is it! Yes!
This competition meant
everything to Miklous!
Oh, boy! Gus!
Gus, here we go!
Gus, it's happening!
I know who killed
Elvin Cavanaugh.
Can't he ever just tell
us to arrest someone?
He does this a lot?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I'm kind of a slave
to my visions. I'm a slave.
Do you want me
to cuff him?
Why would I want that?
Just a suggestion.
They just sort of come
when they wanna come, and...
Jiri.
Spell "soubrette."
Why is this man speaking?
You can't, can you?
Not without help
from your dad.
And that's not a
real inhaler, is it?
This is crazy, this...
This...
Cheating was
Cavanaugh's obsession.
He was gonna expose you
as a cheater.
He was gonna disqualify Jiri,
and you knew it,
and you couldn't
let that happen.
You had way too much
to lose.
You slipped into the box.
You knew his comfort
was food!
He was dangerously unhealthy!
He's starting
to go into shock.
You knew he wouldn't
stop the bee!
He never stops the bee!
By the end of the round,
it was too late!
Too dizzy to walk,
he stumbles...
He tumbles over the rail,
Crashes
onto the chairs below.
And there goes
the evidence.
Except for one thing.
That inhaler.
It sends electronic signals!
The transmitter
is in your jacket.
You sent the signals from
the audience to the stage.
And I bet at your home,
we'll find the van
that ran me off the road
when I alerted the police!
Dangerous cocktail,
unforgiving poisons.
You don't need it.
I took your advice.
I ran the Chinese food through
the lab, nothing's definite.
I'm sorry.
He just seemed sure.
I took a shot.
I'll take it from here.
I could've won
that thing.
Yeah, you could've.
Thank the Lord
you didn't.
What is that supposed
to mean?
Oh, Gus.
The guy who wins?
Saddled forever as,
you know, the dude that
won the spelling bee.
I'm sure you would've
dealt with it later,
but kids, high school
kids, especially,
they're just ruthless,
judgmental.
Horrible little bastards.
You wouldn't have been
able to date a cheerleader.
They wouldn't have invited
you to any parties.
You'd have been
the object of ridicule.
I mean, this way, you got to
be a smart kid and a cool kid.
Best of both worlds.
That's true.
I appreciate that, Shawn.
Yeah, it's a nice balance.
That's why I had to
give you the wrong letter.
You knew that was wrong?
Oh, come on, Gus.
"Aggiornamento"?
Everybody knew
it was an "I".
All right, you hold on.
You were happy
one second ago.
I was about to win!
I studied for three months.
Yeah, and you would have kept
studying forever and ever!
All the way till Nationals!
But you're upset now,
I can see that.
But you'll be fine
with it later.
You know what that did to me?
Yes, yes, I do. We
went out the next night,
and you were so flustered that
you threw caution to the wind,
and you hooked up with Melinda
Castleberg! It was nice!
Come here, Shawn!
At least I was honest.
Come here!
Ah, Shawn, what a coincidence.
Yeah, I was just reading
the newspaper,
a little article that sounded
very familiar about a spelling bee.
Thanks for the help, Dad.
Police ever get
that evidence?
Yeah, a funny little bird
tipped them off.
Leg doing better?
It's getting there,
doesn't hurt so bad.
Listen, Dad, the thing
about the house, the dog,
it was kind of a big deal.
And I know I held a grudge
about it for a while.
But I think
you were right.
A dog needs a house, and a
doghouse needs an occupant,
so as a token of
my appreciation,
I left you
a little something.
Sincerely,
thanks.
Shawn. Shawn!
No. No way!
Enjoy, Dad.
Shawn, you gotta take
this thing with you!
You kidding? There's no pets
allowed in my apartment!
I'm gonna stick it
on the street, Shawn!
I swear I'm gonna stick...
Shawn!
He's not gonna keep
that thing, you know.
It's my neighbor's dog.
Shawn!
Take a lap around the block.
Let him stew a little bit. I'm
gonna take it, and I'm gonna go,
and I'm gonna
stick it on the street!
Shawn! Shawn!
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know