Everyone stay
together, please.
Our next stop
is the primate habitat.
You hear that,
Trish? Monkeys.
We're going to
visit your family.
Knock it
off, Shawn.
Now, some people believe that the
next animal we're going to see
is the ugliest creature in
the whole animal kingdom.
Does anybody want to guess
which animal that is?
It's definitely
got to be Trish!
I hate you,
Shawn Spencer!
Shawn!
I wonder what it is!
Whoa.
Miss Bodansky, I think the
ostrich might be choking.
Oh, I wouldn't
worry.
I'm sure
it's just eating.
Yeah, that's...
That's how they
swallow their food.
I'm pretty sure
that's not food.
A tennis ball, Shawn?
What are you thinking?
What are you doing throwing
a tennis ball at an ostrich?
The thing could have died, and the
zoo would have made me pay for it.
I don't even know
what an ostrich costs.
I didn't do it.
I didn't throw the ball!
Stop lying, Shawn. You're
only making things worse!
Maybe he's
telling the truth.
Are you, Shawn? Are
you telling the truth?
Yes, sir.
Did you see
who did throw it?
No, sir.
But I think it might have been an
accident. I think they meant to hit me.
I believe him.
He's telling the truth.
With all due respect, Captain, you
call the shots at work, not here.
You deal with your kid.
I'll deal with mine.
You, scoot over.
I believe you, Shawn.
Gus!
What?
Gus, Gus, Gus, Gus, Gus!
Come here!
What?
Look at this.
Isn't that...
Trish Connors?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
and her dad.
Whoa!
Wow, she looks...
Hot!
I was going to say vulnerable,
maybe a little upset, but...
I mean, she was cute in high
school, but she sure has grown.
I wonder what Trish and Captain
Connors are talking about?
Why don't I just
read her lips?
'Cause you can't.
Sure, I can.
Shh!
"I'm sorry, father.
"I can't fight
it any longer.
"I love Shawn.
"I'm in love
with Shawn."
"Stop pretending to
be insane, daughter."
Daughter? He calls
her, "daughter"?
"You know you
belong with Gus!
"He's smarter and funnier,
plus he has abs like Bruce Lee."
Whoa! Whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Okay, okay.
If we're gonna do
the lip-reading game,
we have to say things that are
at least remotely believable.
I am.
"Abs like Bruce Lee"?
Dude, they're
coming in!
Act natural.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Oh, hey!
Shawn?
You probably don't
remember me...
Don't speak!
Oh!
I'm seeing
a face...
A face from
the past.
We know
each other.
Yes, we do.
I said no speaking.
Oh, sorry.
We were
classmates.
Yes! Sorry.
Did we ever kiss?
No.
I'm sorry.
That image may very well be coming
from the not-too-distant future.
I'm getting a
name. Connor!
Trish?
Trish Connors?
Wow!
Look at you! Oh, my
God! You look amazing!
What are
you doing down here?
Wait.
Why am I sensing
your father?
Dad!
Yes.
Captain Connors, it is so
good to see you again, sir.
Please,
come in, guys!
Sit down in our
cushy chair!
Dad, you remember Shawn and Gus,
we went to high school together.
I know who
they are.
That's
Henry's boy.
You don't have to speak to
me as though I'm a child.
Now, the
reason that
we came
to see you
is that there
is a...
Um...
Dad, do you want me
to hold something or...
No, no, not
now, please.
I have to just...
Oh, damn it!
Nobody breathe.
I'm seeing something.
Gus.
There was
violence.
Murder.
Yes.
There was a murder.
Yes, exactly!
A murder, a 187,
and I solved it.
You bet your ass!
So, what do you
need us for?
Because, damn it, I can't
remember who's been killed!
Or who
the killer was.
Did you go to the police? Oh,
they're useless, all of them.
Without evidence, they
won't even speak to you.
Thirty years I
spent on that force.
But they still refuse to
believe me when I tell them
that there was a murder,
and that I solved it!
But I'm having
trouble remembering...
Actually,
remembering anything.
That's why I'm here.
To see if you could...
Maybe you could
look into my head.
See what
I can't find there.
But you believe me,
don't you?
Yes, sir.
I believe you.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
So, your Trish says that
this is where her father comes
every morning
for his coffee.
He was here when he
thought he saw the murder.
So?
So, maybe we'll see something
that led an ex-cop to believe
a murder had
been committed.
Plus, double-chocolate
mango-pineapple scones.
Apparently
made fresh daily.
What I'm saying, Gus, the
morning is essentially a win-win.
Oh, no!
What?
Little "i"s.
Gus, little "i"s,
little "i"s. We gotta go!
What?
Little "i"s!
What about Connors? What about the
double-chocolate mango-pineapple?
Forget the scones.
There's only one person
I know who makes the...
Don't rush off
on my account!
Dad!
Shawn, you remember my old
captain, Brett Connors.
Of course.
Captain Connors,
how are you, sir?
Look at you fellas, all grown
up! How long's it been, huh?
About a day.
Less, actually.
Excuse me?
Yes, can I help you?
I don't know. My
name is Sabrina.
Vito.
Sabrina Vito.
And I think that my
boyfriend might be missing.
He hasn't called and he
won't answer the phone
and I'm a little afraid that
something might have happened.
So, I've been putting
these up all over town.
It's okay. Why don't you
come over here and sit down?
Okay.
Oh, that's right,
that's right.
That's right, this chick was
sunbathing naked in the plaza.
No!
You should have
seen your old man
chasing her
with the cuffs.
This gal was so covered
with suntan oil,
every time he grabbed her she
squirted right out of his hands.
And that
reminds me of that 502
that we picked up that New
Year's Eve, over on Olive Avenue.
How do you remember
all this stuff?
Ah, it's easy. Like
it was yesterday.
Speaking of
yesterday, Captain,
is this the table
that you always sit at?
Because I'm getting
something here.
The murder?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you were sitting
here when you saw the victim.
Shawn, what are
you talking about?
Shut up, Henry.
I solved a new murder.
And your boy here's the
only one who believes me.
Now, let the kid work!
I'm seeing a man...
5'9", 5'10" tops.
Shaved head.
Yes! Yes!
Yes, yes...
His name...
Mif...
Mif-you... No.
May? Mick?
Mike!
His name is Mike!
He was arguing
over in the park
with that bastard
Mort Crocker.
A mountain lion...
He pinned it
on a mountain lion!
Now, if I can
just prove it...
All right, look, why don't I
play psychic here for a moment?
It wasn't a young man.
It was a young woman.
She's pretty. Brunette
hair, nice figure,
she liked to play
Scrabble with her friends.
Her name was Zoe.
Yeah,
you're right.
That's who
was murdered.
They said it was a mountain
lion, but they were wrong!
Dad, you're
amazing!
Maybe my psychic
gift is hereditary.
Shawn, Zoe Sharp
is a young woman
who was found dead 20 years
ago, mauled by a mountain lion.
Connors and I
worked the case.
So, she was murdered?
She was in the wrong
place at the wrong time.
A tragedy, yes.
A murder? No.
Not then,
and not now.
Okay, okay, let's forget Zoe
Sharp, may she rest in peace.
But Connors still saw the
guy on the "Missing" poster
arguing with Mort
Crocker in the park.
What?
Shawn, we have no idea what
Connors saw or what he didn't see.
The man is ill.
Early-onset Alzheimer's.
His mind, the past, the
present, it's all screwy.
It's all the same to him. So, he sees
Crocker standing there in the park.
It triggers an old
memory of Zoe.
Next thing you know,
he's living in the past.
Dad, this guy's your friend.
He came to me for help.
Shawn, leave him be.
He doesn't need your help to
make him look like an old fool.
He deserves
better than that.
Shawn!
Run, little alien!
Run!
Shawn!
What? You're gonna
want to see this.
See what?
Look!
Uh...
Coincidence?
I don't think so.
So, when my dad said
he solved a murder,
you think this is the guy
that was killed?
Well...
It seems like a simple
question, doesn't it, Trish?
I'm afraid the answer is
a bit more complicated.
You see, as a psychic, it is
important that I elicit the proper...
I'm sorry. Raise your hand if you
want to know how my amazing gift works!
Gus, you're so
much better at this.
Why don't you tell
Trish how it works.
I've got some
stuff I need to do.
Sure.
The answer to your question is yes,
we do believe that is the victim.
Please. So, what's
the next step?
Well, being that
the authorities believe
he was killed
by a mountain lion,
Shawn is going to
attempt to elicit
a psychic link
with this suspect,
in order to establish
his guilt or innocence.
And by suspect,
you mean...
The mountain lion, yes.
Amazing.
Not really, it's... it's...
It's fairly common for a psychic
to be able to read different
species of the animal kingdom.
No, not that.
What?
The way that he's
sitting there so quiet.
I mean, in high school
he was always so loud,
and needed
attention constantly
to be noticed.
And he just
would not shut up!
He was so annoying.
He drove me nuts!
But now...
I mean, look at
him, he's so...
Calm,
so unobtrusive.
And the way he let you just
step in and take over like that.
I think he's
really matured.
Yeah, yeah, he has.
Dad!
No! No!
He was mauled
by a mountain lion.
You don't find that the
least bit coincidental?
Of course it's
coincidental, Shawn.
But it doesn't
make it murder.
No, it makes it an episode of
When Animals Attack: Santa Barbara.
Yes, well, mountain lions
do attack in Santa Barbara.
In fact, you watch
the news, right?
That's your source
of psychic information?
It happens.
Connors came to me. He
says, "I solved a murder."
Shawn, Connors
was a good cop.
And the thing that
made him a good cop
is that he never
accepted the easy answer.
But that doesn't mean
that he was always right.
Obviously somewhere
in his mind,
he's confused something
that happened 20 years ago
with something
that's happened today.
Okay, fine.
Talk to me more
about 20 years ago.
How does Zoe Sharp
connect to Mort Crocker?
Mort Crocker founded the
Mort's family restaurant chain.
He was the CEO.
At the time, Zoe Sharp was his
assistant, and there was a rumor...
A rumor!
That they were
having an affair.
Nice, that's
good stuff!
And Connors
knew about it?
Of course he knew about it.
Every good cop makes it his job
to know about things like that,
but there was never any
proof, Shawn. No proof!
And even if there was, somewhere
in some corner of his mind
there is a memory,
a lingering memory,
searching
for closure.
But then he sees Mike here
arguing with Mort Crocker.
Connors is not the most
reliable witness, Shawn.
Dad, he's onto
something.
One mountain lion,
two mountain lions!
Mountain lions!
You're right.
You should talk to
a mountain lion.
Whoa!
Simba! I am your father.
I don't think
Mufasa said that.
Ah, Mufasa, Vader,
I'm Not Rappaport,
it's all James Earl Jones.
I'm Not Rappaport
was Ossie Davis.
It still works.
We're not even
supposed to be in here.
Relax. I love cats, and it's
been proven that cats love me.
Well, this cat
likes to eat people.
Here,
kitty, kitty, kitty.
You're not going
to eat anybody...
No!
What's going
on here?
Who authorized you
to be in here?
Uh...
Please, excuse us.
I am
Dr. Hans Jorgenson,
and this is my very distinguished
colleague, Dr. Mc...
Tock.
I am so sorry. I wasn't
expecting you until tomorrow.
Yeah, we have
arrived early.
Well, I'm happy
you're here.
I'm Joan Walker,
the zoo director.
Oh, let's see.
Oh, look!
Dr. Hans Jorgenson.
Look what they have
done for us! Dr. Mc...
Dr. Mc...
Tock.
Mmm.
Oh, what?
Oh, it is nothing.
You see, the Kosov language is
very difficult to master, yes?
It seems you have, uh, inadvertently
uttered a vile Kosov obscenity.
Oh, I am
terribly sorry.
Don't worry.
My colleague only speaks the
English at a very pre-school level,
and he is very
forgiving of others.
For instance, yesterday I poured
a hot cocoa over his genitals,
and I say, "I'm
sorry," and it's fine.
Now, is that
the man-eating lion
that we have
read so much about?
No, no. He's
not a man-eater.
No, no, if he attacked, it's
only because he was malnourished.
So, tell us. Why is the
cat so malnourished?
I really don't know. I mean, we
had record rainfall this year.
There's an abundance of foliage
for his prey to feed on.
He should be fat,
but he's underweight.
Perhaps it is because everyone
in California is on the diet?
Yeah? All of the surfing
boys and the model girls.
I mean, someone, anyone, please
give them a sandwich, yeah?
Meatball, uh-huh?
What is that?
The cat doesn't look
like it's eaten in weeks.
Doesn't make sense.
Yes, this is Joan.
Oh, well,
where's Dr. Zamfir?
Actually, no, no,
stay right there.
I might have someone
who can help us.
Seems we have
a bit of a situation.
One of our warthogs is ready to give
birth, but our vet is away on an emergency.
Could you please ask
Dr. Mc... The doctor,
if, as a distinguished
veterinarian,
he would please help us bring
a new warthog into the world?
Please excuse
while we confer.
Meercat...
He would be
honored, yes.
So, just
lead us the way.
Thank you, thank you.
What are you doing?
We don't know anything about
delivering warthog babies!
Oh! A baby is a baby, you just
pull it out at the right time!
The real question is, are
you allergic to placenta?
Oh, God! My eyes!
My eyes!
Again, Mr. Crocker,
thank you for coming in.
I know how hectic
your schedule is.
Don't mention it,
Detective Lassiter.
I'm never too busy to help
Santa Barbara's finest.
Why don't you tell
me what this is about?
Did you see this
in the paper?
Yes, I did.
Sad.
We have information that you
were seen with the victim
the day before
his body was found.
No, it wasn't me.
Why don't we just
cut to the chase?
It was that detective,
Connors, wasn't it?
20 years and he still
can't let it go.
I really can't say.
Mike's body was
found on this trail.
It's closed.
Now what?
Just hold on, let
me think a minute.
Okay.
I have a plan.
It's a
little crazy,
but it might
just work. Okay.
What?
Dude, we totally
made it. We're in!
Shawn, in case
you're confused,
"closed" means,
"go away." "Stay out."
Yes, in the negative
language dictionary,
which is clearly the
only edition you own.
But in the positive
language edition,
closed means, "Come in,
step over the chain,
"there's so many less people to trample
all over what you're looking for."
You really think you
can track the animal?
Perhaps you've forgotten
about my extensive experience
with the Native Americans,
a proud and solvent people.
Working at the
Flaming Tomahawk?
So, you
do remember.
Shawn, you were a greeter
in the casino, for a week.
The only non-Native American
to be awarded an eagle feather.
Always remember that,
Gus. Oh, please!
Black lab! Akita!
Lizard.
Okay, now you're just
making stuff up.
Flamingo.
What if we do find these
mountain lion tracks? What then?
Well, we clearly follow them to
the kill zone and look for clues.
What kill zone?
What?
Felis concolor. It's
Latin for mountain lion.
Let's follow them,
and see where they lead.
This is it!
What?
The kill zone.
The kill
happened here.
Except...
Except what?
Except the drag marks are
coming from that direction.
The lion tracks we
followed are over there.
If this lion dragged
and killed its prey,
the tracks and the
marks should match up.
They should come from
the same direction.
Gus, you know
what this means?
The murder
didn't happen here!
Exactly.
This cat was framed.
I guess you guys can't
read. This area is closed.
What are we
doing here?
I'm burning up
in this thing.
No you're not.
Yes, I am.
You've been wandering lost
in the woods for two nights
and you're suffering
from extreme hypothermia.
Now, shiver!
How are you
feeling? Better?
Oh, Ranger De Soto,
this soup is amazing.
Gus called it a chowder,
and I'm tempted to agree.
Do you think you might have
any crackers to go with it?
Perhaps those
little oyster kind?
I'll check.
You're too kind.
Crackers? Really?
For someone who supposedly
drinks his own urine,
your palate is suddenly
very sophisticated.
Let's get out of here!
We can't.
We've got
work to do.
I think there's more to this
gun-toting ranger than meets the eye.
Like what?
Well, for starters...
He just happens to know the infamous
Mort Crocker and his wife, Edna.
Coincidence?
Shawn, it's
a fundraiser.
The Crockers probably posed
with everybody in there.
What about the
giant cage outside?
What about it?
I suspect that
at one point,
our man-eating mountain lion was kept
in that cage, and sustained a small cut.
Yeah, when they trapped him
and took him to the zoo.
Sorry, all I have is
saltines. Is that okay?
Oh, believe me, when you're
starving, you'll eat anything,
including the poop
of indigenous beasts.
Speaking of which, when
we were lost out there,
Gus here was
little-girl-scared
that we might be eaten by
some kind of wild animal.
Does that sort of thing
ever really happen?
Well, it's not unheard of.
Fact is, we had a guy killed by a
mountain lion just a couple of days ago.
Does that kind of
thing happen often?
Oh, a few times
in the past 50 years.
I thought mountain lions
were afraid of humans.
Generally, but if
they get hungry enough...
We've had a really dry year,
that means reduced vegetation,
and reduced vegetation means fewer deer
and the like for the lions to feed on.
You can't really
blame the cat.
It gets hungry
and it wants to eat.
You mind if I ask you a question
that's completely unrelated?
Sure.
Is that real
mahogany?
Now, what
do we know?
We know there was
plenty of rain this year,
no reason for a mountain
lion to be malnourished.
Why was
Ranger De Soto lying?
Why do people
usually lie?
He's hiding something.
Henry Spencer
back from lunch yet?
Henry Spencer?
I'm sorry,
who are you?
Never mind.
Just tell him
to come and find me.
We need to go over
that Zoe Sharp file again.
Whoa!
Excuse me, sir.
You can't go
back there!
What the hell
is all this?
Captain Connors?
Yeah.
May I help you?
This is my desk.
Look, son. I don't know who the
hell you are, but you're confused.
This is my desk.
It's been my desk for years.
Now, you can either help me find
the Zoe Sharp file, or take a hike.
You know what?
Maybe there's
someone we should call.
Hey, look, I don't have time for
all this crap. I've got work to do!
Sir, please. Don't
make this difficult.
Hey, you wanna
dance, pal?
You just name
that tune. Come on!
I don't know,
Shawn.
Accusing Crocker of
murder's a pretty big deal.
It doesn't bother you that we're
missing things like motive,
where the murder took place, or
any kind of evidence or proof?
News flash, Gus, the
cops think I'm a psychic.
I just have to get a
feeling at the right time.
Shawn! Gus! What
are you doing here?
My father,
he's disappeared.
Hey!
Come on.
Where?
All right, now you are starting
to piss me off, old man.
Come here!
It's time
for you to go.
Henry! Henry!
Tell them
who I am!
Um... I think he's
talking to you.
Oh, God, please tell me I don't
look anything like my father.
You could be his twin.
Look at the back of my head. Is
my hair starting to thin at all?
Shawn!
Henry!
I think we all
know who this is.
This is Captain
Brett Connors,
one of the finest
cops in the SBPD,
someone I'd be happy to
share a squad car with.
What the hell is
going on, Spencer?
This man happens to be
my friend, now let him go.
He's your responsibility.
Get him out of here.
Let's go,
Captain.
I should report them
all to Internal Affairs.
They should be
brought up on charges.
I couldn't agree more. You head
home, I'll draw up the paperwork.
That's
the girlfriend.
I'm sorry
to disturb you.
Was his
name Mike?
Yeah, it was.
How did you know?
Shawn Spencer,
police psychic.
I know that this must be
a very tough time for you.
Sabrina.
Sabrina...
I am so sorry
for your loss.
You know, he'd
come all this way.
Lived so much, and his whole life can be
condensed into a few items in this box.
Mike wasn't
from here, was he?
No, no, he was visiting.
Yeah, that's right. We
were both from Pennsylvania.
Mike came out here to
search for his birth parents.
I am sensing
a longing.
He was so sad the first
time he called me.
He just found out that his
birth mother had been dead
for almost
20 years.
And that would explain the
sadness that I'm feeling.
But then a few days
later he called to say
that he thought he had
located his birth father.
I'd never heard
him more excited.
Did Mike bring another pair
of shoes with him on this trip?
No, no. Just what
he had on him.
It was pretty sudden,
this trip out here.
I see.
Sabrina, I'm feeling that Mike
does not want you to be sad.
Can you tell me,
did Mike get to meet
his birth father?
He said he was a really wealthy
man and difficult to get to.
Yes.
Yes, he did.
A biotin deficiency
can be hereditary.
It's not exactly
a paternity test,
but let's see if Crocker
has the same prescription.
If so, we know
Connors is right.
This is
a fortress.
We need a plan.
I don't think we can exactly
just ring the buzzer
and ask to peek into Mr.
Crocker's medicine cabinet.
Why not? That sounds
perfectly reasonable to me.
Why can't we be
from the state board
of medicine cabinet
inspectors?
I don't know, Shawn.
I know I'm right
on this one.
Let's think
this through.
No, Gus. Come on, let's
go in without a plan,
flying by the
seat of our pants.
It'll be so much
more fun, trust me.
See, look, man. There's some
kind of commotion happening here.
Planning a party.
It's a piece of cake.
They're never going
to notice us.
Excuse me, where
are your badges?
Oh, I don't need a badge,
I'm the event planner.
The event
planner's a woman.
Yeah, I'm her
assistant.
Also a woman.
To the
assistant.
I'm calling
security.
No, no, no, no! You
don't need to do that.
Don't tell me what to do. The
rules are very strict here.
Really? You're going to let your
bosses run you around like that?
You're gonna let the
man hold you down?
These freak bastards with
their rules and regulations?
You're a human person!
You need to rise up and
tell them all to go to hell.
We can all do it together!
Let us empower you.
I'm Edna Crocker,
and you are one minute
away from a squad car ride.
Probably ought to let
this one go. Yeah.
Hi.
I'm here to pick up a
prescription for a Mr. Crocker,
Mort Crocker.
One moment, please.
Thank you.
See, you should listen to
me every once in a while.
That's not fair.
I don't have access to medical
files and doctor's names.
Shawn, I called
two pharmacies,
while you were
being interrogated.
I don't have anything
for Mr. Crocker.
Are you sure
about that?
Yes.
Um...
Can I just get back
there for a second?
I'm sorry, we don't
have anything,
and someone has already picked up
all of his most recent prescriptions.
Is it that bastard,
Jimmy Derukie?
Shawn, please.
I'll tell you what,
before I go a little nuts,
why don't you just
give me the name
of the prescriptions and
we can get out of here.
Okay, okay, see, it's a
long-standing prescription.
It needs to be renewed. No
one's gonna go nuts here.
Okay, no,
I do have something,
but they picked that
up over two months ago.
Really?
What was that?
The penicillin?
No, it was his regular
dosage of something called...
Biotin.
Yes, is that what
you're looking for?
Yes. Thank you.
All right, Spencer.
You said you found an eyewitness
for Mike McMillan's murder.
Where is he?
Okay, Mike.
Go ahead.
Tell the detectives
exactly what you told me.
You're kidding
me, right?
And we're
out of here.
Mike says he was in town searching
for his natural birth parents.
If you don't believe him,
you can ask his girlfriend.
That's true.
She told me.
Did she also tell you that
he found his birth father?
Well, what about his birth mother?
Did Mike say if he found her?
No, no. He didn't
say anything.
See, he can't.
He's a picture on a piece
of paper, and dead.
You should be
ashamed of yourself.
Mike said his mother
was killed 20 years ago,
right after
he was born.
Her name was Zoe Sharp.
I knew it.
That son of a bitch.
He killed her and now
he got rid of the baby!
He protects his business,
his reputation,
and he doesn't have
to share his wealth.
Sounds like a motive
for murder to me.
Really?
Yep.
Then how do you explain
the mountain lions?
Huh? You're so smart?
How do you explain that?
Lassi, why are you
asking him?
He was just a baby when
his mother was killed.
In fact, he wasn't
even there.
Summer of '86
was hot and dry.
There were
a lot of fires.
Lions were all
going hungry.
I remember some of them came
right into town looking for food.
Crocker killed Zoe and
dumped her body in the hills.
He didn't know about the
lions, that just happened!
They ate the evidence
and covered his tracks!
He just got lucky!
What about
this time?
With Michael, he
just got lucky again?
No, not this time.
This time he had help.
- Ranger De Soup...
- De Soto!
De Soto provided
the lion.
De Soto?
I know that name.
I just can't
remember why.
Sir, it's okay.
Well, I got to hand
it to you, Spencer.
This is a
terrific story.
There's just
one problem.
Sir, it's nothing that Mike
can't help us work through.
What is it? Crocker
has an airtight alibi.
He was in Chicago
when Mike was killed.
Oh, he's lying.
No, I checked
it out myself, sir.
He spoke at a symposium in
front of 200 other people.
No, no.
Not again.
Not this time.
Hey, Dad!
Sir!
Daddy?
He wouldn't do anything
stupid, would he?
Define "stupid."
Go up to
Crocker himself?
Trish, come on!
Children, no running!
Jane! So nice to
see you. You, too.
How do
you do?
Mort Crocker,
you're under arrest
for the murder of Zoe
Sharp and Mike McMillan.
Mr. Connors, I'm so
glad you could make it.
Why don't you help
yourself to a drink?
No, no, no, no.
You might fool all of
these people, but not me.
Is everything all
right, darling?
Everything's fine.
Please go back to...
Captain Connors, sir, why
don't you let us take you home?
Pardon us for
the disturbance.
Oh, crap!
Hey!
Connors!
Oh, come on! Stop
acting like a child!
Dad?
Bless you.
Thank you.
Shh!
He was here.
Well, of course he's here.
We saw him come in, Sherlock.
No, no. Not
Connors. Mike.
Mike McMillan
was here.
What?
But you sound
all muffled.
What are you
eating something?
How can...
Right, right, right.
My bad.
He was muffled.
It was my fault.
There. There,
that's so much better.
Please get
out of here now.
I don't allow anyone
inside my greenhouse.
Well, that's not exactly
true, now, is it?
You let Mike McMillan
in, didn't you?
I mean, this is
where you killed him.
You see, when Mike's spirit
started talking about Crocker,
I thought he meant Mr.
Crocker, but it wasn't.
He was talking about
Mrs. Crocker.
Well, for your sake, you had
better be right this time.
He came to see you,
but you weren't here.
What?
Mike, you know I
don't speak Italian.
Shoes. He wants you
to check the shoes
that he was wearing
that day. The soles.
You'll find potting soil in the
tread that matches that stuff.
Edna, what's he
talking about?
Edna?
God damn it!
That's why I
know the name.
Before you were married,
your name was Edna De Soto!
And you and your brother John, the
park ranger, were in this together.
He used the lion
to cover your tracks.
You're not really going to
believe this old fool, are you?
Watch who you're
calling... What?
I'm sorry, that was my fault, I
just wasn't paying attention to you.
Are you serious?
It's in a bird feeder?
No, I'll say it.
There's a surveillance
camera out front.
Apparently
it's in a bird feeder.
If the tape wasn't erased,
you'll be able to see him
arriving on the day he was killed.
Please, Edna,
tell me you didn't.
What was I
supposed to do?
Someone had to protect everything
we've worked so hard for!
You would have given
him half of everything!
Just like you would
have his mother.
He was my son!
Detective,
arrest this woman,
and while
you're at it,
issue a warrant for the
arrest of John De Soto,
for the murder of Zoe
Sharp and Mike McMillan.
Officers, you
heard the captain.
Get them
out of here.
Dad, I'm so
proud of you.
Showoff.
Good for you.
Yeah, thanks.
It's a real honor,
you know.
I thought these days
were long gone.
Does that mean you're
coming out of retirement?
What, are you kidding?
I'm lucky if I
come out of the fog.
Well, you gotta keep
your brain stimulated.
Try the crosswords.
Nah, I like that
Sudoku.
Well, we could always
go after cold cases.
Nah, best leave it
to the young guys, huh?
Thanks for giving
him this day.
I hope he remembers
it tomorrow.
He couldn't let go
and move on, you know?
Shawn?
Yeah? What?
I'm sorry, I...
A little... Little lump
in my throat.
Speaking of lumps...
Yes?
The ostrich?
The tennis ball?
What?
You know what? It's not
a big deal, obviously.
But it always
bugged me a little.
Why didn't you
say anything, Trish?
Like what?
Oh, I don't know.
"I threw the tennis ball into the
highly restricted ostrich area,
"and I let you take
the fall for it."
You're serious.
It's not too late
to make it right.
Right is right.
You really still have
not grown up, have you?
Wow.
Goodbye, Shawn.
Gus.
What?
Hey! There she is!
Hey!
No, no, here.
There, are
you happy?
Yeah, actually,
I am.
Good.
Good?
You really want me to believe that you
put your foot in your mouth deliberately?
Please.
Go get the girl.
It's your move.
No.
Listen, would you go...
Shawn, I told you.
I do not need you to lay
back for me to get a girl.
Get over there.
No.
Show her the abs.
Not until you challenge me
straight up!
Fine.
I will be
kissing Trish
in 10 minutes.
Not if I get
there first.
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know