"For every action, there is an
opposite and equal reaction."
Who? Isaac Newton,
third law of motion.
And how does that apply to the
nature of man? Anyone? Shawn.
You push, they push back.
Correct. Why?
Because man is
a stupid creature
who'd rather fight
than use his brain.
And what idiot said that?
You did.
The name of the game
is survival, sports fans.
In order to survive,
you've got to fight.
And if you fight,
you better damn well win.
Because if you don't win, and you don't
use your brain, then what happens? Gus?
You lose?
And for this troop, that
is not an option. Comprende?
Sir, yes, sir!
Because losing is for lowlifes.
Losing is for quitters.
Are you boys lowlifes?
Are you boys quitters?
Sir, no, sir!
Troop 101, ten-hut!
Gentlemen,
we are about to embark on
the Junior Bobcat Manual's
infamous Exercise Number 32,
the launching
of a solid fuel rocket.
Now, one of you lucky grunts
is gonna nab this thing
and you're gonna
haul ass back to me.
The prize?
A hot fudge sundae.
But if you lose? What
does the loser get, Shawn?
He gets to
look on with envy.
That is correct.
He gets to look on with envy.
Because that, gentlemen,
is the American way.
On your marks.
Ready.
Set.
Go!
What's this?
A parachute.
I sent you after a rocket.
Shawn?
Where's my rocket?
I thought he had it.
A shortcut!
You took a shortcut!
A shortcut, huh?
Prove it.
I'll tell you what,
I beat you this time,
I'm eating the sundae.
Ooh, just in time.
For what?
The annual Civil War
re-enactors meltdown.
The event isn't
until next weekend.
Yeah, but this is the
best part, the rehearsal.
This is what
they should charge for.
Form battle lines!
Prepare muskets!
Is that Lassiter?
Yes, it is.
What died on his face?
Charge!
Stop, stop, stop!
Stop!
Okay, guys,
that was better.
Really.
It was good, actually.
Okay, it wasn't good.
Look, guys,
I know I promised last week that I
wasn't going to give any more notes.
But, guys, come on,
that last charge, it was...
How do I say this?
It was a
soul-sucking embarrassment
that made me ashamed
to wear the uniform.
Luke Bauer?
Where's Luke?
Colonel Lassiter, sir!
Luke, what did I say
about the bayonet gag, huh?
Too much. There's gonna be
kids watching this, all right?
We don't want the people
in the grandstands to vomit.
Okay, I know we haven't
reenacted this one for a while.
But the battle at
Piper's Cove, Kentucky, 1864,
is special to me.
It ended Confederate Quantrill's
plot to assassinate Lincoln.
And it involved my great-great-grandfather,
Colonel Muscum T. Lassiter...
Muscum?
What the hell is a Muscum?
It was a very common name
of the era.
History Channel.
ESPN, Gus. Channel 206.
I'm begging you.
Hey, Jules!
Wanna join?
Oh, can I?
I don't know. Do you
have your own hoopskirt?
I rent one.
Sally Reynolds,
front and center.
You missed your cue, Sally.
The cannon fired,
yet no Sally.
I got stuck
in the hospital tent.
Sergeant Menish had a quick question
about his homeowner's policy.
How touching. However, today you are
not here to sell insurance, Sally.
Today you are here to
help me win the Civil War.
And according to
our battle plan,
when the fifth cannon fires
you exit the hospital tent
and you shoot Captain
Quantrill off his horse.
There's no need to get nasty.
I agree.
It was totally out of line.
Sorry, I didn't think
you could hear that!
Sally, sweet Sally.
If you do not point your
gun at Captain Quantrill
and fire at
the prescribed moment,
the audience will not be able to make
heads nor tails of what we are doing.
And it will appear as if
the evil Captain Quantrill,
now being portrayed by our
horrifyingly method-acting Nelson Poe
who happened to roll
way off his mark, by the way,
fell off his horse
and is lying here
for no apparent reason at all.
Get up, Nelson.
Nelson, I swear to God, if you're
sleeping through rehearsal again...
I said get up!
Okay, either that guy is
a phenomenal actor
or he's dead.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Oh, come on, let
me in on this. No.
I was there. Inexplicably
drawn to the scene.
I was meant to
solve this case.
It's sort of
like a miracle.
You have been out there every
weekend we've rehearsed.
And don't think
I didn't see you
trying to throw M&Ms in the
injured soldiers' mouths.
Okay, first of all,
those were Skittles,
and they have
a rainbow of flavors.
The answer is still no.
Beat it.
Oh! Hold it!
I'm suddenly seeing Nelson.
The bullet,
traveling through the air,
tearing, ripping, pain...
The bullet went
straight through his heart.
This was not
an accident, Detective!
I don't know how you know that,
and I don't give a rat's ass.
This case is personal.
One of my soldiers was
killed on my watch.
And I, not you,
am going to clean it up.
We clear?
I wouldn't have gone with something
as traditional as "we clear?"
You could've gone foreign,
right? Comprende? Capisc?
Could have had a little fun with
it. You dig my gist, sweetpants?
These are just suggestions.
...and to you, the Central
Reenactment Committee,
I say as of today, the event
next weekend is still on,
pending an investigation.
Now, most of you are cops.
Should we find any evidence that this was
not an accident and do not make an arrest,
we will re-evaluate
at that time.
Now that said,
Detective Lassiter,
I want to know how, I want to
know who, I want to know why.
Oh, it...
It's kind of hard to get off. It
takes a long time to unstick the glue.
All right.
- Ooh!
- Oh, yeah.
Thank you, Chief.
Pending the coroner's report,
I'd have to say there are
no indications of foul play.
The general consensus is that a live
round got mixed in with our blanks.
Mr. Mahoney is the regiment's
munitions expert and jeweler,
one of Santa Barbara's
finest. He can expand on this.
Mr. Mahoney.
As you know, Detective, we
had live-round target practice
this past weekend.
Along with you,
we assumed a musket ball
got stuck
in one of our rifles,
laid there unseen,
and then a blank was inserted
during the last rehearsal...
Poor Nelson. A terrible,
terrible, tragic accident.
The battles meant
so much to him.
Anyway, this is an official
police investigation.
So let's focus on our schematic
and nail down the specifics.
Detective O'Hara,
please.
Hey.
What's the deal, why do
you keep staring at me?
One. It's our understanding
that the victim was shot
off his horse
at the top of
the creek bank here...
And then rolled
to the creek bed here.
Two. We know Nelson
was facing west,
so we're gonna
focus our attentions here
on the opposite bank where
we assume the shot originated.
Assume.
Detective?
Spencer?
What about three,
the missing bullet?
I saw it ripping
through Nelson's body,
in through the front,
out through the back.
And it still
hasn't been found.
Wait.
How do you know all that?
Lassy,
you wanna take this one?
He had an "episode"
in the hallway.
Look,
I can handle this myself.
Nelson, Nelson, you're going to
have to speak up. You're teeny!
You were shot
through the heart?
Now, that was
privileged information!
I didn't say anything.
Are you sure about this?
It's bold,
but I'll run with it.
He says people don't get shot
through the heart by accident.
He says he was murdered.
You're hired.
You told them what?
Gus, she was hot, and she
was dressed as a nurse.
You know
how I feel about that.
Oh, come on, what was I
supposed to do, not impress her?
Plus, the tiny figurine made
a very convincing argument.
I don't know how you're gonna prove
murder with two lousy bullet holes.
Oh, relax. I did some checking
on Nelson Poe, nobody liked him.
Ever.
And second of all...
What?
Dude, I don't have
a second of all.
And we know Nelson was on top of
the ridge, facing the Union soldiers
over here when he was shot.
So Schwartz, take Team A,
check out that high grass.
O'Hara, take Team B,
start going over the ridge.
Do it.
Yes, sir.
Find something amusing?
Mildly amusing.
More odd.
Delightful,
in a queer sort of way.
For your edification, the
reenactment of the battles...
Edification?
Yeah, edification.
Is that legal? Like, in public.
Public edification's legal?
It means
for your information...
Why didn't you
just say that?
For your edification,
the reenactment of battles,
battles fought by our forefathers
to preserve this Union,
is a sacred trust.
What are you guys
doing here, anyway?
I'm a bit of
a Civil War buff.
I'm reading the dirt.
The trees.
The hot dog stand.
No real information there,
but they do great sauerkraut.
I may even be able to
help you name a suspect.
Look, I told you, we're 95% sure
this was an accidental shooting.
What about the other 5%?
If I am wrong, we will
hold a press conference,
you two will be cordially
invited to say "I told you so."
Seems fair. Hey...
Can I wear your face wig?
What are you doing?
Shockingly,
Lassiter is holding out on us.
I do not think that he thinks
that this was an accident.
What do you mean?
I saw three names checked off
the roster on his clipboard.
What names?
Gus,
I thought you'd never ask.
What is this?
The battlefield.
Based on what? The briefing
room board at the police station.
You did this from memory?
Yes.
You said you saw it
for two minutes.
Right, two whole minutes.
You got problems.
Factoid! The musket is
accurate from 30 yards.
Poe.
G.C.
G. C?
George Cheslow.
George Cheslow?
From sixth grade?
Little Georgie!
He's, like, a dentist now.
Really?
See you in six months.
We go in,
we check it out.
See if George Cheslow had
any reason to murder somebody.
Pop out.
Mr. Guster.
The dentist will see you now.
Sweet.
Whoa!
Me? My teeth are gorgeous. You
said the appointment was for you.
Right. For me to
do some snooping.
Because I'm a much better
snooper than you are.
You just keep him occupied.
Occupied how?
Gus, stop it. Be a man.
What's he saying? He says
his teeth are gorgeous.
I'm sorry, Shawn, but the reason
you have to be here, too, is?
George, Gus has phobias. And being
alone in a dentist chair is one.
He could snap at any moment.
This is actually
for your own protection.
Last time
he bit off an index finger.
Thankfully, I was there. They were
able to save everything but the nail.
Oops. Pardonne-moi.
Honey, can I talk
to you for a minute?
Oh, sure.
Gentleman, duty calls.
Oh, and the credit card won't
go through. Do you have any cash?
Oh, sure.
I've got tennis,
then dinner with Karen.
Okay, I'll hit
an ATM, that's...
Don't wait up if I'm late.
Oh, okay. All right. Bye,
sweetie. Good shopping.
Ah, yes.
George, I heard you got
married, but, wow, huh?
I know what you're thinking,
"What's wrong with this picture?"
But, you know,
where is it written
that the ugly guy
never gets the girl?
Everywhere, man.
Yeah.
No, we're fine. We're better,
you're fine. Don't worry about it.
Let's see here.
So how is married life
treating you these days, George?
Everything...
Everything solid?
Why are you
snooping around here, Shawn?
You think I did this
because Erlene was
having an affair with Poe?
Huh?
You didn't know.
Of course I knew, George.
I'm a psychic.
It was over, completely over.
I'm beyond it
and Erlene's beyond it.
At least,
I think she is. I...
I had some gauze...
It's right...
If I could just...
Oh, there you go.
Thank you.
George, do you wear your
glasses out on the battlefield?
Oh, I want to,
but Lassiter won't let me.
He says they're not
of the period.
Well, if it makes you
feel any better,
Gus here doesn't think
you did it.
Neither does Shawn.
Well, thanks, guys,
I appreciate that. Oops!
Oops?
Small cavity.
I don't have
any cavity in my mouth...
It's right on the surface.
Don't worry about it.
There we go.
There's my trooper.
Listen, Georgie, nobody's
drilled my mouth for anything...
George?
Why am I surprised?
It is a funny coincidence.
Hey, Jules.
George,
I hate to say this,
but you're under arrest
for the murder of Nelson Poe.
What?
On what grounds?
You said
it was an accident.
We discovered a stack of
love letters at Nelson's house
indicating he was having
an affair with your wife
and that you had
threatened to kill him.
Oh, come on.
I am so disappointed in you.
All right.
Okay, okay, okay.
You got the wrong man.
What did he say?
You've got the wrong man.
First, I told you so.
Secondly, I think George
Cheslow is an innocent man.
Yeah, you know, he's right.
We do have a paper-thin case.
I mean, all we've got is
motive, means and opportunity.
Look, guys.
I had a dream last night.
I was sipping iced wine
with a baby tree monkey.
And I fell and I landed
in a wooded area.
And that's where
I saw Nelson Poe get shot.
Only, in my dream, the shooter was
much closer than I originally thought.
This is a minie ball,
am I right?
Where did you get this?
Your desk.
Now, it's common knowledge that minie balls
cause huge gaping holes in human flesh
which leads to
a quandary in my dream.
Why was Nelson Poe's
exit wound so small?
If George Cheslow had been
in that wooded area,
he was way too far to make a shot
that caused such a little hole.
Whoever shot Nelson was
much, much closer.
And this "whoever" would be...
Engelbert Humperdinck.
So you've got nothing.
Thank you for the random
speculation. Goodbye.
Mr. Spencer, if you can't name names,
I'm afraid he's right this time.
Fine, I'll get you a name.
And I'm gonna
get you a woman.
"Afraid he's right"?
"This time"?
It's a gift, actually, for
my son. A surprise of sorts.
This way he, my son, will be able
to keep track of time for a change.
Kid was late at birth,
he's been late ever since.
Now, he is going to have a gold
pocket watch just like mine.
I've had mine for 30 years.
I see. Now, the inscription.
What would you like it to say?
"Shawn,
"don't lose this watch,
Henry Spencer."
Spencer.
What, too much?
No, no. It's just that your son is
no doubt familiar with your last name.
It might contradict
the sentiment.
All right,
what would you suggest?
"Love, Dad"?
"Love, Dad." Well, why don't
you just put "Kissy, kissy"?
Right, too mushy.
No problem.
So, before we go any further,
let's see.
Vintage gold pocket watch.
Gold chain.
Taxes and engraving,
comes to a total of...
Wait, wait, wait.
Where's my discount? I'm
ex-cop. Half the regiment's cop.
I thought we agreed on $400.
Oh, yes, we did.
But at $4 per engraved letter,
that adds a total of $210.
All right, take away "Shawn,"
"this watch", "Spencer."
How much does
that come out to?
$56 for the engraving
plus tax,
$460 even.
And what does
the revised inscription read?
"Don't lose, Henry."
Clean, to the point.
I like it.
Come in.
Mr. Guster, I know you said you
didn't want to be interrupted,
but there is a Lieutenant
Crunch here to see you.
Crunch?
Actually, I've been promoted.
It's Captain Crunch.
Thank you.
Not in a thousand years.
Dude, we're joining that
regiment. No, we are not.
They're down to 30 guys.
Please, I have a meeting in...
And this mystery is
still wide open.
Gus, think about it.
Camping out under the stars.
Living history. Eating beans and
rotten meat with men who reek of valor.
There's just one thing
you haven't considered
in this perfect scenario
of yours, Shawn.
That's not true.
I've considered everything.
Really? And what role would I
play in this production of yours?
I don't... What do you...
What role would I play
in the midst of
all those hardcore
down-to-the-last-detail
Civil War re-enactors?
Would I be...
No.
Gus, no.
Okay, then maybe would I be...
Never.
Who are you talking to? You're
talking to me. This is me.
Then what, Shawn?
What would I be?
Because I tell you, there is no way,
no way, that I would ever, never ever...
May I please tell you
what I was thinking?
What?
I was thinking Glory.
I was thinking Denzel.
Did you just say Denzel?
As in Denzel Washington?
No, the other Denzel.
Of course. And we'll
put you on a horse,
and we'll give you
your own sword.
You're gonna have
a chestful of medals.
You can be anything you
want. You can be a pilot.
The Air Force wasn't
formed until World War I.
That's fair.
So you can't be a pilot.
Look, I called Mr. Mahoney,
he's Mr. Uniform,
and I told him to make you
something spectacular.
Denzel Washington.
Captain Mahoney, you said
we needed recruits? Voilà.
Welcome aboard, son. I didn't
expect you back so soon.
Don't know if
the uniforms are ready yet.
But it is spectacular?
You saw Glory?
This is the best we had.
Well, come along.
I told you.
Wow, Captain, it's quite
an establishment you've got here.
My sanctum sanctorum.
Fine jewelry, yes. Even my
vintage pocket watch collection.
But above all, the finest
Civil War memorabilia
and props
west of the Mississippi.
I can attest to that. I've
repaired nearly half of them.
Sally. I am so happy
to see you,
though I'm a little disappointed
you're not wearing your nurse's uniform.
Griffin called me, frantic,
saying we needed one more outfit.
You okay with that?
I sure am. It's just a shame
you didn't dress me.
Still time for that.
Aside from reenacting,
Sally insures
half the regiment.
Auto policies, homeowners.
Even theft.
Speaking of which, Griff, I'm
thinking of insuring my legs.
Sort of like Mary Hart.
What do you think,
three, five million a haunch?
Keep in mind my calves are
like carved marble.
That's not the kind
of policy she writes.
So she wrote yours?
Of course. And it's worth more
than both your legs put together.
Does that policy include
plastic explosives?
'Cause I see that you're
packing C-4. Is this authentic?
Better yet,
is it even legal?
For the reenactments. We
fudge the fireworks sometimes.
Our audience goes wild
every year
when the fake cannon fire
showers them with dirt.
What do we have here?
C.S. Richmond High Hump. .58-caliber
percussion loader. Iron ramrod.
Good Lord, Burton,
you are a wonk.
What the heck?
Sorry. Sorry. The battlefield
can be pretty messy at times.
What about these jars
with the buttons in them?
For the super hardcores. They
soak their brass in urine.
You ready
to try this thing on?
Sure.
Dude, you look awesome.
Are you sure there's
not another uniform?
Yeah. But, I'm checking
with the Ventura Association.
Personally, I think
you look dashing.
I always loved
the marching band.
It's not so much me as it
is Mickelson. He's good.
Shawn, we're supposed
to be roughing it.
Gus, for your edification,
they don't have TiVo out here.
Hi, Sally Reynolds.
Keep an eye on
those patties.
Shall we?
Let's go somewhere dark. You
can give me a history lesson.
Captain Quantrill, he's the guy that
burned down the abolitionist town?
Lawrence, Kansas, 1863.
A year later they were hell-bent
on assassinating Lincoln.
But Lassiter's great-
great-granddad, Muscum,
he stopped 'em cold
on the bridge, yeah?
Sort of like
a noble calling, right?
Something like that.
And the nurse you portray,
who's that?
Jenny Winslow.
She lost her husband
and two sons at Lawrence.
She wanted revenge,
and she got it.
And what about you,
Sally Reynolds?
What do you want?
Shouldn't you already know?
Why, because I'm psychic?
My aunt used to think
she was a psychic.
She got predictions wrong
all the time.
Then she'd get the smallest
random detail right,
and she'd say, "You see?"
So, what you're saying is
that you doubt me?
That hurts my feelings.
Well, you still haven't
guessed what I want.
Damn it!
Shawn? What happened?
Gus.
I know how Nelson Poe
was killed.
Good morning, Father.
Good morning, Your Highness.
I lost your pocket watch.
The truth, Shawn, you're
not really my son, are you?
Because I gave you a watch with
the inscription "Don't lose."
And what is
the first thing that you do?
I lose the watch.
You lose the watch!
Well, here's a news flash, Dad.
My birthday wasn't yesterday, okay?
It was four months ago.
Yeah, well, here's
a newsflash for you, kid.
After you were born, it took
you four months to smile at me.
That's when the clock
started ticking.
Look, Shawn, I appreciate this newfound
respect that you've got for time,
but what the hell are you
doing out here in the boonies
with an antique
gold pocket watch?
I don't know, trying to clear an
innocent man named George Cheslow?
It's a button.
All right, look,
this case of yours, I...
I've been thinking
about it and...
Really?
What? No,
I haven't been "thinking."
Look, killing your wife's lover
is something that's rarely planned.
It usually just happens.
So even if this dentist
Cheslow did plan it,
he's not gonna be some numb nuts
hanging around waiting for love letters
that're gonna point the cops
in his direction, right?
Exactly. He's not gonna hang
around like a numb nuts.
So here's the deal. I think
Nelson rolled into this creek
and was shot from that tree
right up there.
And you figured
this out last night
when you fell on your ass
down here by yourself.
Right on my ass.
Now all I need to do
is find the missing bullet.
And how and where do we find
this missing bullet?
How about right here?
Shawn, what about the watch?
You mean this watch?
Hey, I needed
a metal detector.
Target was out of stock. And you
won't let anyone use yours, so...
Hey, I found the bullet.
Well, hey, you didn't find
the killer, did you?
You need to find
the killer.
Hell of an exit.
P.S., you look like an idiot.
I am warning you, he'd
better not be wasting my time.
Honestly, Detective, I've never
seen him so excited before.
"Four score
and seven years ago..."
Shawn!
"Ask not what your country
can do for you..."
Shawn! "...but
what you can do for..."
Gus? Is that you?
Shawn!
Yellow! All I see is yellow.
Yellow and the number two.
I'm already getting
a bad feeling here.
There's lead. No, graphite.
Fine, I'll play. A pencil?
Yes, a yellow pencil.
You see a yellow pencil?
Yes.
Where?
I'm not sure. Please,
help me, Detective, please.
A little to your left.
Back to your right.
Oh, you are getting warm,
you are so warm!
Oh, gosh!
You're burning up!
How can you stand that?
Great, you found a pencil.
Now we can all take the SATs.
There's more. The evidence,
the critical evidence,
it's there, just look closer.
Look closer.
That's it. Gus.
That's it. That's the
bullet that killed Poe.
And I bet when I run it through
ballistics, it's gonna match
George Cheslow's musket.
No, you're wrong,
it's not Cheslow.
O'Hara. Yeah.
We're on our way.
It's a 439 in progress.
Four thirty-nine?
Yeah.
We gotta go.
Wait, I was...
I'm not finished!
There's more!
E-mail me!
Juliet!
I found the bullet! I...
Should we go?
No.
No. Let's run through this
from the killer's
point of view.
Okay, Nelson was shot
from up here.
Let's do a list.
Okay. One.
The killer climbs
the tree, like so.
Right. Two?
He gets ready
to shoot from here.
Three.
Three. Nelson rolls down the
creek, way past his mark.
Four.
Looks up, sees the bad guy.
Okay, which means Nelson
wasn't the original target!
Bingo.
He interrupted the plan.
Okay, look up there
and see if you see a notch.
You know,
that would steady a gun.
A notch.
Yeah, like a notch.
It should lead us
to the intended target.
That's not a notch.
That's a notch.
The hospital tent.
Dude, I think I got it.
What?
Sally Reynolds.
Sally Reynolds?
Why would someone want
to kill Sally Reynolds?
I have no idea.
Folks, our Civil War
re-enactment has begun.
Hey, what's up, guys?
You're going to get a call
from a very irate Sally Reynolds
saying two guys just drove by and
stole her dress. Just ignore it, okay?
What the hell are you guys
doing? Sally was the target.
Shawn's gonna put on that dress
and wait for someone to shoot him.
Right, but the plan sounds a lot
better when you don't say it like that.
Listen, Detective,
we have reason to believe
that the intended target
was Sally Reynolds.
Now, we've stolen her dress
and we're gonna catch the
yellow-bellied son of a bitch red-handed.
I forced the ending,
that's horrible.
So, risking getting shot is
the only way to solve the case?
Absolutely. Then we
should stop the battle.
No, we can't.
It's too late.
They're gonna start in less
than a minute. Listen, Juliet,
please let us go?
I can't let you do that.
You're a civilian.
It's too dangerous.
It's fine.
We'll spot the guy well
before he gets a shot off.
I'll do it. I'll do it.
What?
Juliet?
Charge!
Careful, Gus!
Sorry!
Just take a deep breath.
Okay.
I don't think these dresses were
intended to fit over a bulletproof vest.
Remember, we will be out
there watching. Got you.
To catch the bad guy before
you get shot. I understand.
But just in case, I want you
to bob left, weave right.
Traditional bob and weave, no
reason to get fancy out there.
And don't become
an easy target.
I did go to
the academy.
Or you could die.
Right.
Now remember, the fifth
cannon boom is your cue
to shoot whoever's
playing Quantrill.
Right. Wait,
how do you know that?
I read the manual.
Didn't you?
I didn't open the manual,
it was like War and Peace.
There were 17 chapters.
It's the manual, Shawn.
- It was this thick...
- Hey.
- Sorry.
Sorry, sorry, sorry. All about you
right now. All right, you're a champion.
Now go out there
and catch us a killer.
Juliet, please be careful.
And don't die.
How many times you gonna
say die? Shawn, just get...
You're putting the word "die" into
her head. She knows there's a killer!
Guys?
Yeah?
A favor.
Sure! Name it.
Kick me.
Do what?
- Kick me!
- Okay!
Now what?
Now we get ready
to find a killer.
Here it comes.
The moment of truth.
Where's our killer?
That's weird. Nobody came.
Well, at least Juliet
is out of danger now.
What?
Well, I wonder
where this leads.
Watch your head.
Oh, did you get sewage
on your feather?
We've crossed to the other
side of the creek bed.
Yeah, the police accounted
for all of the Union soldiers.
But nobody's considered that the
murderer could have come from this side.
After all, this was
the bad side, right?
You know that's right.
May I ask, who goes out on the
battlefield without their boots?
Maybe someone has bunions.
Bunions, Gus? Really? That's
what you're bringing to the table?
I'm trying to solve
a murder here.
I deal with bunions
at work every day, Shawn.
They hurt...
They hurt people.
That's a perfectly
logical assumption.
Oh, yeah? What about
this? No tunic.
This is Mahoney's!
What?
The brass button.
Mahoney did it.
That's why he had
that sticky musket.
He must've gotten sap on it
from that notch in the tree.
Wait. This doesn't track. Why kill
Sally? She's hot, they're friends.
She even wrote
his insurance policy.
That was C-4!
That didn't come from the
battlefield, it came from the south.
I solved the crime.
No, I did.
I said it first.
I identified the uniform.
I found the button near the tree. I
said it first. Tap, tap, no take-backs.
That's not fair, Shawn. I
was identifying the C-4 sound.
Dude, you snooze you lose,
Gus. I don't have to tell you.
That manhole we found
connects to the sewer.
It's going to lead us right
to our killer. Let's go.
We're going in by ourself?
What, are you crazy?
Where you going, Mahoney?
Hey, Griff!
Hello, boys.
Back off. Back off.
Back off. This gun is loaded.
Yes, but mine are
so much bigger.
Get out of the way,
I'm coming through.
What the hell is
going on down here?
Colonel,
arrest this traitor.
I'll have that weapon,
Captain.
Okay, hold on, I'm gonna need
you to walk me through this.
Mahoney blew up
his own vault?
That is an absolutely
outrageous... Shut up!
Not only did he blow it up,
he used the battle as a cover
to rob his own store.
Then, he'd collect a multi-million dollar
insurance policy in a couple of weeks,
then slip back to the
battle during the cannon fire
with no one ever
being the wiser.
Oh, ye immoral
man of low fiber!
You should really
eat more bran.
I want to see my lawyer.
In due time.
Wait, but I still don't
understand. Why kill Nelson Poe?
That is the rub, isn't it?
Sally Reynolds was
the intended target.
The question is why?
Hi, Juliet.
Got your message.
What the hell is going on?
Oh, I can see it
clearly now.
Sally wrote Mahoney's multi-million
dollar insurance policy.
That means she...
She was in on the fraud
from the start.
That's a lie.
But Mahoney here didn't want to share
those millions, so he gets an idea.
What if sweet, sweet Sally
with the filthy mouth
and the bedroom eyes
had a little accident
out on the battlefield
during the rehearsal?
You mean Griffin tried
to kill me? That's right.
This is a lie. You are fabricating
everything you're saying.
Now you hold on a second,
Mr. Mahoney.
Oh, hey, Gus, you see, when
Nelson rolled down the creek bed
and landed too close
to the river, he looked up
and he saw Griffin in the tree
with his trusty musket, who said,
"Griffin, now you must
kill Nelson Poe
"to keep his
stinking mouth shut."
Told you you had
the wrong person, Lassiter.
I know.
Detective O'Hara... Lose the hoop
skirt before you hurt someone.
Read 'em their rights
and book ' em.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Hey, it was good work,
Detective. We got 'em.
"We"?
We're a team, right?
Gus. When we grow up,
think I'll ever be as cool as you?
You're better at kickball.
Not what I asked.
We talking about
your dad again?
Mmm-hmm.
Come on, dude.
The guy respects you.
Not like he does you.
I'm not his son.
I mean, he might like me okay,
but he loves you.
Did he say that?
No.
Then how can you be sure?
You mean he's never said it?
Come on, Gus. We're guys.
Charge!
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know