B4.
Miss. A7.
Hit.
D9.
Miss.
B6.
Hit.
Shawn!
What?
Hey!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
Knock it off.
Knock it off!
What the heck
is going on here?
Mr. Spencer, your
son's been cheating.
Have not! Are, too! You
hit my ships every time.
Both of you,
on your feet, now.
Best friends do not accuse
each other of cheating.
Best friends do not resort to fighting
every time they have an argument.
You both know that I have a
partner on the force, right?
Yes, sir.
Well, we couldn't do our job if we
didn't trust each other completely.
There are rules
to a partnership,
and they are the same rules
for a friendship.
Even Battleship.
But those rules don't work
without what?
Trust, sir.
That's right.
Shawn! Over here now.
Why aren't there any of
your ships on the board?
I knew it!
Cheating? You're grounded.
But, Dad!
And for the next two months, you
are gonna play with one less piece.
But that's not fair.
Exactly, Shawn. Now you
know what it feels like.
Shawn, I can't just
give you a case
because Gus is out of town
this weekend and you're lonely.
Fine, maybe together we can figure
out how I can be less lonely.
Wait, I'm getting
something.
Baby oil.
This is a photo
from about a year ago.
Oh, thank you.
And this is
from last week.
Thank you. We'll call you if we
turn anything up on her, Mr. Sirtis.
I appreciate your help,
Chief. Our pleasure.
I'm telling you, I can
make the time, Chief.
Your plate is full,
Detective.
I already pulled
the old file.
If any of your
other cases suffer,
then I will yank you
right off of this...
Spencer, what the hell
are you doing?
Trying something.
I feel conventional vision
is weakening my skills.
Is that my scarf?
I...
I'm getting serviced.
Return service.
No, a net.
Fishnet? No!
I love somebody.
Now I'm getting Grecian
Formula. That's weird.
It's not about what's there,
it's about what's missing.
Tennis equipment.
No, a tennis player
is missing.
Björn Borg is missing!
No.
Who's missing?
Congratulations, Mr. Spencer.
You've just joined the case.
What?
We can all pitch in.
Deanna Sirtis was supposed to meet her
father Leonard at the airport last night.
They were flying to Tokyo for a
tournament but she never showed up.
The last time anyone saw her was
at tennis practice that morning.
Has anyone checked out
her stalker?
Felix Alvarez?
We're looking into him, since we know
he broke into her house a few months ago.
But what we need
from you now
is to psychically locate
Deanna
while we follow leads
using conventional methods.
You mean, Lassy and I
can work together?
Yeah, but separate.
Should we synchronize
our watches?
You're not wearing a
watch. That's a good point.
Chief, I'd like to put in a
requisition order for a new watch.
Lassy, can you
sign for that?
All right, that's enough.
Just... Now, let's go
do your jobs. All of you.
Hey!
Thank you.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Gus! Gus! Gus! Gus!
Hello?
Dude, how long
until you come back?
We just got here.
Yeah, but you can come home
during the weekend, right?
This is a weekend, Shawn.
It's a retreat,
with trust exercise
to build up a sense of
teamwork around the camp.
Camp? You didn't say
you were camping.
Are you making S'mores?
Can I have some?
Have you done "Who's Got My
Golden Arm" yet? Let me come do it?
Shawn, what do you need?
Have you ever heard
of Deanna Sirtis?
She's a tennis player. Local.
Ranked in the low 100s.
She's a missing tennis player.
Ranked 147th.
And she's our new case.
I can't, Shawn.
Reingold just retired.
Ah, yes. Reingold.
What the hell
does that mean?
It means they're reassigning
his clients, Shawn.
He has this one doctor
with a huge practice.
Dr. Magnotti.
He prescribes in bulk, Shawn.
I'm talking Costco bulk.
I could make my monthly quota
in like a day.
But to get him, I gotta
schmooze my supervisor.
So you're on our own
this time.
Gus! Guess what, Gus?
Hold on.
We just elected you to be the first
one to hold the "sharing stick"...
What? ...in the
"sensitivity circle" tonight.
All right, this is great.
Okay.
All right. Oh, gosh!
That's funny. It sounded like
someone just said "sharing stick".
Dude, get out of there!
I have no choice. I hate
the stupid "sharing stick".
But I couldn't get out of
this even if I wanted to.
I've taken care of
that already. Burton!
Why haven't you
painted yourself green?
Excuse me?
We're all painting ourselves
green. It's an envy-retention thing.
Oh, it doesn't matter now.
I just heard about your
grandmother. My grandmother?
Slipped in the tub?
Broken hip.
Oh! Go square her away and
get back as soon as you can.
Well, at least we won't forget
what she looks like.
My daughter definitely
liked having her photo taken.
I think it's what she
liked most about winning.
Photography was
her hobby, too.
But we don't have
a lot of time for hobbies.
You keep a security camera
in her room?
That guy, Felix Alvarez,
the one the cops
are looking for now.
After he broke in,
we beefed up security.
I remember reading
about that break-in here.
It must have been
traumatic for her.
Yeah. It felt like she never got
back to her former self as a player.
Mr. Sirtis,
the spirits can be bashful.
Yeah.
Sometimes grumpy,
sleepy, dopey, sneezy...
Shawn. Shawn!
What I'm saying is,
they won't talk to me
unless no one is in the room
except myself
and my compatriot.
That's me.
That includes
security cameras.
I'll get it turned off.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Cameras in her room?
Can you say control freak?
Can you say
typical sports dad?
What?
These diamonds pretty
much nail the four C's.
I bet they're from daddy.
Yeah?
Except for this one.
Look.
This is way too cheap.
See how the gold chips off
when you slide it around?
This is from somebody else.
Somebody who's not loaded.
This is an eternity ring. You're
supposed to wear this all the time.
And it's usually given to you
by someone, you know, intimate.
Why do you know that?
I gave one to Jessica Chan.
Ah, yes, Jessica Chan.
And how long was eternity
for the two of you?
Three months.
But they were awesome months.
Except for the end part.
Right. I've never
seen a girl lie
about entering the Witness
Protection Program.
She wasn't lying, Shawn!
Gus, I saw her at Starbucks!
You can't be sure of that.
She was wearing a nametag.
She had a plaque on the wall.
"Employee of the Month." Her hobbies
were hiding and lying about hiding.
Fine. Whatever. Drop it.
My point is, why isn't Deanna
wearing hers all the time?
She clearly has someone
daddy doesn't approve of.
We find the mystery lover,
we find her.
Dude, why don't I ever
get to say stuff like that?
All right. Get her down to
the station and take her statement.
Nail down the last time
she saw Deanna.
I'm on my way in now.
I am sensing you're
drinking a nonfat vanilla,
half caf with lots of whipped cream
but without your usual pink straw.
What, are you two
stalking me now?
Or did you come to tell me
where the missing girl is?
No.
But I did divine that Deanna
has a secret boyfriend,
which sounds
like a lead to me.
Yeah, we're looking into
all her relationships.
But, you see, it's my job
to investigate people
with things like, you know,
motive, means and opportunity.
Stop following me.
What did I say?
Look, man, I've been meaning to have the
same conversation with you about leading me.
To be honest,
I'm sick of it.
We either walk side
by side, or not at all.
Shawn, six months ago
I called you up
to ask you whether or not
you wanted any of this junk.
How come you only call me
to come pick up stuff?
You didn't listen, now I'm
donating all of it to Goodwill.
I'm on my way there
right now,
so you got about 30 seconds,
last looks.
No, no, no.
You cannot throw out
my Whitesnake T-shirt.
You can't get this
in stores anymore.
That is...
This is my
Airwolf windbreaker.
I've been looking for this
for like five years now.
Why did you take this? I
never even saw you wear it.
Of course I didn't wear it.
I took it, so you wouldn't.
Don't put it on.
Gus, nobody had an Airwolfjacket
except Jan-Michael Vincent.
This looks like a custom
Sak-Hart graphite rod and reel.
That's right. Good eye.
You can't throw
something like this away.
It's 15 years old.
Fifteen? Looks brand-new.
Oh, that's because
it's never been used.
Bought it for him.
Man, I have been itching to get out
on the blue and hook some snapper,
but you know what a chore
it is to get the boat and...
You're welcome to come
with me tomorrow morning.
Boat leaves
at 5:00 a.m. Sharp.
Princess here,
never could get him up.
Look, the American Medical Association
clearly states the proper amount of sleep...
Well, if you're sure you
don't mind a little company?
If you're sure
you can be there at 5:00 a.m.
I'll be on the docks
at 4:15 a.m.
Spencer.
What just
happened here?
I think your dad just
made his first play-date.
It's not funny.
It is.
He gave away my custom something
something pole. I loved that thing.
You gonna get it back?
No. We are going to the Vista
Rico Health and Racquet club.
Now's not the time
for a steam, Shawn.
Gus, Deanna was seen
practicing there
the morning she disappeared.
If she's some sort of tennis star,
she probably goes there a lot.
Maybe someone saw her
with her mystery lover!
How did that sound?
It feels like you're
pushing. You're pressing.
Deanna's coach
is in Tokyo,
but the manager said this girl was here
practicing the last time Deanna was.
Sweet.
Excuse me, can we talk
to you for a second?
I only have 11 minutes
left to practice.
Yeah, but isn't it better if someone's
over there to return your serve?
You play? No, but this is
Vernest Lambert Watkins.
He was a junior champion
of some junior league.
What did you guys call yourselves?
The Little Green Fuzzymen?
The Yellow Hornets. But
that was like 10 years ago.
He'll give you a workout.
We're just gonna have a chat.
Racket's over here?
Now, I can sense that you were
here the day Deanna disappeared.
Duh. Everybody knows we hit
together. What are you, a genius?
Actually,
I'm a psychic.
And I don't think
I like your tone.
Let me rephrase that, and don't
read anything into my tone,
why do you think she didn't show
up to that tournament in Tokyo?
Out.
Out? Out my ass!
You can't be serious. That
ball was clearly on the line!
Long. Long by
a hair, buddy.
Any ideas?
You know what
her weakness was?
Kittens?
Focus. All she thought
about was boys.
Cowboy up there, buddy.
Shut up.
Any boys in particular?
She was not particular
at all.
But I heard she started hanging
out with that Doug Lenmar.
Doug Lenmar? He's one of the
top-ranked players on the men's tour.
He stinks. No net game.
Her father totally freaked when he
found out and told her to end it.
Then she tried to be all rebellious
and stormed off the court.
How grody of her.
Grody?
Grody to the max?
Grody with a spoon.
Come on, work with me. I don't know
what the kids are saying these days.
I don't remember anything
else. That's all I heard.
Well, you hear a lot.
Coaches are more gossipy
than housewives.
Just watch. In five years,
she'll be knocked up and living
in government assisted housing.
It's good to see
the game hasn't hardened you.
Out!
Okay, so we know she had a
secret boyfriend, Doug Lenmar.
But if he was in Tokyo,
why would she go to see him?
Let's find out
if he really is in Tokyo.
If so, plan B.
She was boy-crazy.
There's got to be more
than one dude in the mix.
Maybe she's not missing.
Maybe she's hiding.
To keep her dad off her case.
But where would she hide?
Ooh.
What?
I have the urge to suddenly
get my bunions buffed.
Shawn, this is
completely unnecessary.
Deanna was here.
We have to retrace her steps.
In a paraffin wax dip?
You know how flaky
my knuckles get.
Two birds, one stone.
I've never felt so productive.
And exactly how much information
do you plan on getting
from a manicurist
that can't speak English?
None so far.
Hold on.
Dude.
Hurry up!
She was here yesterday.
Check that out.
Gus, you're gonna
smudge my gloss.
She ordered
nail protein solution.
So she has weak,
peeling nails.
No, genius. The billing
address is her father's place,
but the delivery address
is someplace else.
Nice focus, Gus.
Thank you.
Maybe you're ready to take
on that little girl again.
Gus, I feel good
about this.
She's gonna be here.
Safe and sound.
Or not.
All right, I want to talk to
her the minute she wakes up.
If she wakes up.
What happened here?
This isn't a missing
person case any more.
It's attempted murder.
Man, even she gets
to say stuff like that.
That's more crappy jewelry.
That means the working-class
boyfriend has been here.
Hey, aren't you
Henry Spencer's kid?
That I am.
I took a six-week course
he taught at the academy.
Lucky you. How was he?
Yeah, that just
about sums it up.
Do you mind if we
poke around a little?
No.
We do. We mind
quite a bit actually.
You know what,
scratch that.
I'm gonna let you guys stick around
to see what real detectives do.
Sweet! Just let us know
when they arrive.
Deanna shared this place with
another player on the tour,
so her name wasn't
on the lease.
But Lassiter found
one of her close friends.
Apparently, they met frequently
at that Indian restaurant.
We canvassed the area
with her photo
and the owner of this building
recognized her.
So we opened the
door and voilà. Voilà.
O'Hara, come
take a look at this.
Check this out.
I think these were all
taken inside this apartment.
I think you're right.
Wait a second.
What?
I see something!
I see a trophy.
But I'm out of place.
I've been kidnapped.
There is a trophy
missing from here.
And we know she suffered
a blunt force trauma.
Possibly the weapon.
Good work, O'Hara.
O'Hara? That was all us!
I think your tutorial in police
work is done now. Goodbye.
It's cool. I've got
everything we need.
Deanna is listed as critical
but stable for now.
She's touch and go
for the next 48 hours.
...50 pounds and is
considered to be armed and dangerous.
Anyone with information as
to the whereabouts of this man...
Gosh!
Finding Deanna lit a fire
under the department.
Lassiter's been having
these advisory alerts run 24/7.
So let me
get this straight.
Their theory is that Felix
followed her to her hideaway,
and showed his love
by trying to kill her?
Not a terrible theory.
Let's review, shall we?
No forced entry.
That means she either let the
attacker in or he had a key.
Sounds like someone
she was intimate with.
Now, the toilet seat
in her apartment was up.
So we know there was
a guy there recently.
I doubt the killer stopped
to use the little boy's room,
so let's assume the phantom
boyfriend stopped by for a matinee.
And there were two wine
glasses missing from her set.
So she probably shared a drink
with him, and he grabbed the glasses
which had his fingerprints on
them as he beat a discreet retreat.
None of that points to Felix.
I gotta get back to work.
Now?
You're gonna leave now?
When we're up to our necks
in intrigue?
The case is almost closed. We
have the girl, she's still alive.
The cops beat us.
Let them have this one.
How can you be so negative?
Easy. I need face time
with my boss.
I already missed the
pamper pole trust exercise.
I'm uncomfortable with you even
saying the words "pamper pole".
Look, every minute the cops
spend looking for Felix,
the real attacker
breathes easier.
Now we have got to convince them
to start looking for other suspects.
No.
Unless you can give us something
more substantial, Mr. Spencer,
we're gonna continue the
manhunt for Felix Alvarez.
Manhunt?
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, I can project Tommy
Lee Jones from The Fugitive
if you'd like.
I want a hard-target search for
every outhouse, henhouse, cathouse,
waffle house,
House M.D.
House of the
Long Shadows? What?
Crime scene photos,
Detective.
It's about time.
Were you on a break?
Hey!
Dad?
Now what?
I just stopped by to drop off
this hat for Mr. Lassiter,
so he can look the part next time
we go out and catch us some snapper.
Thanks.
The next time
you go out and...
Isn't that my hat?
What are you doing here?
Oh, you know, just interrupting
an official briefing,
and being in general,
pain in my ass.
Oh, well, try living
with him for 17 years.
Excuse me. I have
a killer to catch.
Good luck with that.
And time!
Nicely done.
Excuse me a second.
What're you doing here?
Dude, you turned off
your cell phone.
Some might take that as a
hint. As in, "Leave me alone."
Burton, you're not
having visitors, are you?
You know my policy
on visitors.
He's not a visitor...
Jerry Hathaway.
I too work at Central Coast.
In the lab.
Yes, I worked on the
mono-thio-Huxtable drug.
It's for pancake-
reactic function.
Pancreatic.
Actually, no, Burton.
It was pancake. Really?
Yes, there are properties in the
batter that help to stabilize
the ions
we were working with.
I never heard
of that project.
It was a great drug.
But it caused headaches,
stomach aches, tooth aches,
weight gain, weight loss, balding,
sever oily bowel discharge,
and in very rare cases
it made you pee fire.
Wow!
Yeah. So the higher-ups
shelved the project,
much to my chagrin.
I thought I knew
all the lab guys.
I'm surprised
we've never met before.
I don't make much of an
impact on other human beings.
It's terrible
for my self esteem.
In fact, I've been here
all weekend,
and this is the first
conversation I've had.
And, Tom, you should know
that nobody made me a nametag.
You know what we say
about that here. Hello.
Hi, Tom.
No, I mean the motto
of the weekend. H-E-L-L-O.
Lop off the last letter and you've
got what this weekend really is.
Stands for Health, Esteem,
Life, Love and Openness.
Well, that's
pretty keen, Tom.
You know, in the spirit of openness,
I've always looked up to Gus.
He's everything
I wish I was.
Do you think maybe we could work
on the next exercise together?
No, we can't do that.
Burton!
I believe your friend
is reaching out right now.
I think you two would be perfect
candidates for the Minefield.
Burton, you have to
keep your eyes closed
while your friend leads you
through a series of obstacles.
Oh, Tom! That sounds
really bitching!
Can I talk to him alone
for a second? Sure!
Oh, great, thanks!
Oh, gosh.
Dude, I've got bad news.
What?
Deanna's doctors say she
showing signs of improvement.
Shawn, in the health care
community, we call that good news.
Given what we already know?
Did she know her attacker?
Yes.
Does that mean when she
wakes up she can ID him?
She ID's him and the case is
closed. Where's the downside?
Because if you're
the bad guy
and you know that your victim could
wake up and point the finger at you...
He'll find
her and finish her off!
You're just not landing it.
The point is,
Deanna's life is in
danger now more then ever,
and she needs us.
Burton, is there a problem?
Yes, Tom,
I'm afraid there is.
Burton's grandmother just
called. She's broken her hip.
I thought you dealt
with that issue already.
The other side.
Tore the M.C.L.
She did it while trying to
do her line dancing classes.
Why was an 87-year-old woman with a
broken hip attending a line dancing class?
Attending?
She was teaching it.
You leave my grandson
alone. He's a good boy.
Oh, yeah. Then why did he
run when he saw us coming?
Because you guys got my face
plastered all over the TV
for something I didn't
do, man. I'm innocent!
I don't even think
about her anymore.
Yeah, see, that's what
all the crazy stalkers say.
Stop!
Just... stop.
Hey, what the hell?
What are you doing?
Get your hand off him.
He's reading his guilt.
Give him a second.
Hamana, Hamana,
Ricky, Enrique, Heraldo,
Menudo, Richie!
This man is
true to his word.
He's pure of heart.
He made many mistakes
in his past.
Dirty, filthy mistake.
See, I'm not telling you anything
you don't already know here.
But he didn't attack Deanna.
Really?
If he's so pure of heart,
why did we find the trophy that she was
nearly bludgeoned to death with in his car?
The raven crows
only at midnight,
dusk is for
the rooster's cackle.
What?
Jules, that's your cue
to cackle.
Shawn, I don't have a
cackle in my repertoire.
What, you called for
this secret meeting.
We should use code-speak
in case people are listening?
It's not secret.
Just away from prying eyes.
So what do you propose?
Should we rent one of those pedal
boats that looks like a swan?
We could, or you
could just take these.
What is this?
Copies of the files
on Felix Alvarez.
Why are you giving
this to me?
I've talked to the kid,
his grandmother
and the court-ordered
psychiatrist he had to see
after breaking
into Deanna's house.
They all say the months of counseling
paid off. He was rehabilitated.
And he had a medical condition
that required dialysis.
My great-aunt
needed dialysis,
and she was always knockdown-dragout,
winter-bear tired afterward.
And his last appointment
probably left him
way too winter-bear tired
to stalk and attack Deanna.
Exactly.
And just what did the
police do when you fed them
this peculiar piece
of info-gristle?
They spit it out.
In fact, they're so
certain that he's the guy,
they've taken the 2
4- hour guard off of Deanna's hospital room.
Jules, that's no good. You gotta
get security back on that door.
The killer will come
back. He'll try again.
At the very least, her dad
is always by her bedside.
Have you seen that dude?
She needs more security than
a 60-year-old in a track suit.
Look, without protection, you might as
well just send the killer an invitation,
saying, "Hey, come on
back, finish the job."
I wonder if they make
invitations for that.
I don't see why not. You can
send an evite for anything.
This is true.
Lassiter thinks it's an
inefficient use of manpower.
I'll see what I can divine.
What's this?
It's rest of the paperwork
on Felix's first break-in.
I figure you need all this
information to do your psychic stuff.
I can feel these two crimes were
not committed by the same person.
But in order for your
brothers in blue to be wrong,
we're saying
Felix was framed.
We're saying it was somebody who knew
he would be targeted by the police.
You're saying it. I'm
stealthily lending an ear,
I'm saying it was an
excellent, slam-dunk frame-up.
This somebody was a
pretty bad guy. Yes.
Ugly on the inside.
Thought of every detail. A
virtual hunchback mastermind...
Shawn! Just let me know
what you find.
And remember, psychic intuition's
not gonna help this guy.
Evidence will.
Oh, one more thing.
Roosters don't cackle.
I beg your pardon.
They cock-a-doodle-doo.
You've got
to be kidding me.
Shawn, what are
you doing here?
I don't know.
I guess I took a wrong turn and
ended it up in The Twilight Zone.
What the hell's
going on here?
What? We caught us
some lunch this morning.
Hooked them, cooked
them and ate them.
How tribal of you.
Shawn never really was
one for roughing it.
We went camping once, found him
curled up inside his sleeping bag
because a raccoon
was hunting him.
Stalking me. The raccoon
was stalking me, Dad.
And I came to
talk to you. Alone.
All righty.
So, what's wrong?
All right,
here's the thing.
Why is there a picture of
Lassiter on your refrigerator?
That's a picture
of the fish.
I didn't even know
he was in there.
What could you guys possibly
talk about out there?
Shawn, that is the
beauty part. Nothing.
He knows to sit there,
shut up and fish.
What? You think we sit out there,
we yap about you all day long?
I can't really wrap
my brain around any of it.
All right,
so what's so important?
I'm working on a case.
And I know that they've
arrested the wrong guy.
What makes you so sure?
The M.O.
Right? This guy in custody, he
trashes a girl's house, trashes it,
but then, at the apartment when they
find her, it's practically sterile.
I'm talking about
a perfect crime scene.
But I cannot find anything in
these police reports to back me up.
Right there. You see, right
there. That's your first problem.
What?
The police reports.
Shawn, a police report is always
from somebody else's point of view.
I've written
a ton of them myself,
and one thing you cannot do
is take them as gospel.
All right? So let's
run this again.
Now you've been to
both crime scenes, right?
Right. Well, the first one
was after the fact,
but I've been
to both places, yeah.
Okay. So...
close your eyes.
Dad, I didn't come here to take a
stupid test. Can't we just talk as men?
Shawn, would you trust your
old man for once, just once?
Close your eyes.
Here we go.
All right, now I want you to go
back to the first crime scene.
This poor girl's house.
What do you see?
What do I see?
Her bed.
Tennis trophies.
Jewelry box.
Mostly nice jewelry.
A wall of photos
featuring her.
Come on, keep going.
Keep going, Shawn,
what else?
No, there is nothing else.
The guy was there
way before me.
Everything looks
different now.
Okay. Okay. Now let's go
to the second crime scene.
To this apartment
where she was found.
Can we stop on the way
and get donuts?
Shawn, focus.
Keep your eyes closed.
What do you see?
Wait a minute.
Thank you, Dad. I have a
crime scene to break into.
I can't believe you pulled
me out of my retreat.
I can kiss my chances of getting
Dr. Feelgood on my route goodbye.
Gus, what time
do you have?
Where's your watch at?
It's a key tanning month.
2:15 p.m.
2:15 p.m. Right.
It's around the same time
we were here before.
So, why are
all these clocks wrong?
Dude,
I need you to lay the ground,
pretend like you're Deanna.
I am not pretending to be a woman
half beaten to death, Shawn.
You know what?
I am starting to wonder if
you have trust issues with me.
Really?
Yes.
First, you wouldn't do
the Minefield,
now you won't lay on the floor and
pretend to be an unconscious woman for me.
What's going on with you?
Two words.
Airwolf windbreaker.
Okay, two more.
Battleship. Dude, that was
like a million years ago.
I'm just saying.
I never cheated again. Now
can we please just do this?
What is the point in me
pretending to be Deanna?
Something here's weird,
okay?
When I was with my dad, I realized
the shadows coming off those two lamps
were in the wrong spots.
I think someone tampered
with this crime scene.
Who could do that?
Someone smart.
Someone experienced.
Which is why we need
to recreate the scene
so that it is exactly the way
it was when the cops got here.
All right. Fine.
Fine. Now,
in the landlord's statement,
he said the body was found
here in the supine position.
So, please, if you will...
Sure. Just tell me
what supine means.
Gus, supine.
Su...
Mmm-hmm.
...pine.
You don't know what
the word means, do you?
Okay, fine. You win.
Mr. Vocabulary wins.
Mr. Vocab is the big winner
tonight, everybody.
Thank you.
No, please, please.
It means on your back.
I knew that.
No, you didn't.
Okay.
This is off.
The lamp is in the same spot,
but the shadows aren't.
And something else
is wrong.
There are six pictures
on this bookshelf,
there are six pictures
in this photo.
What do you expect?
Seven.
I clearly remember
seven photos, Gus.
There were two pictures on
each shelf and one shelf with one.
That's seven.
It was right here.
Where this box is.
Can you remember
what's in the missing photo?
I'm not...
sure.
What the hell is going on?
Nothing, man.
Nothing?
Is that guy dead?
Damn it.
Now you've seen too much.
I didn't see anything.
Yeah, you did. You're in
this just as deep as I am now.
We're gonna have
to work together.
Okay?
I assume this building
has an incinerator? Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
So we just have to
chop up the body
and then we put the limbs
in little plastic baggies.
The torso, we're gonna have
to melt down with a blow torch.
Okay, I've heard enough.
Chop up his body?
And then you wonder
why I don't trust you?
Are we done yet?
One last thing.
Hurry up, Shawn.
Shawn, I left my retreat to solve
a crime, not to order takeout.
That's exactly
what we're doing.
Hi, there. What time do
you turn those lights on?
At 5:00, for the beginning
of the dinner crowd.
Never any earlier for
any reason whatsoever?
It's on a timer.
What the hell is the point?
I think I know
who the killer is.
Just one more question. And
this is absolutely critical.
Do your samosas come
with that red onion chutney?
I arraigned
Felix today.
If he's smart
he'll just plead out.
Next is the...
Jimminy Crickets. What?
He's sensing an anomaly
in the space-time continuum.
Oh, it's very serious.
They can unravel
the fabric of reality itself.
We've been trailing it from across
town. The distortion is near.
Bless you.
Thank you.
It's in the photos
in the file!
Yes. The photos are lying.
That is the anomaly.
It was the distortion that prevented me
from divining dirty Deanna's attacker.
But now,
now I have a clear image.
We already know
who attacked her.
He's right, Mr. Spencer.
He's wrong.
The bludgeoner is close.
Follow me.
Yes! No! No.
Bludgeoner.
What, are you nuts?
He works for us!
The photos.
Look at the
photos. Jules, Jules, Jules,
what's going on with the lights
in the background, in the window?
Oh, he's right. The lights in the
restaurant are on in these photos.
They were off
when we found Deanna.
What?
This is crazy.
Why would I attack some
woman I've never met before?
Never met? Didn't you photograph her
house when that Felix guy broke in?
Yes, that's when
you met her then. Dude!
She liked meeting new people.
And she liked to party.
And she liked to have
her photo taken.
And guess who takes
photos for a living. You!
And it was nice,
and it was on,
and you were giving it
to her, and she liked it.
Until she met somebody who could afford
to buy her nicer jewelry than you.
She was on her way
to see him in Tokyo.
You decided to confront her
at her apartment.
Hey, trophy!
And then
you cleaned it all up,
and you made it nice, and you
left a perfect crime scene.
Then you came back here, and assumed
your capacity as police photographer.
You scrutinized the photos,
making sure there was no trace
of your presence in that apartment.
Oversight.
This bag. Sure enough,
in a photo on her bookshelf.
Your bag with your initials,
that the police have seen
a million times.
They'd have known it was you.
So what did you do?
You waited for the forensics guys
to split, and you snuck back inside.
You were meticulous.
You took the time to turn the
clocks back to the right time,
and you re-photographed the whole
scene without the incriminating photo.
And you re-submitted those
as the originals.
But I can feel
that you forgot
to reset the clocks to the
correct time before leaving.
Oh, Gus.
Take him into custody until
we figure this whole thing out.
So the
prophecy has been fulfilled.
What? What are you talking
about? What prophecy?
Nothing. I just figured it was finally
my chance to say something dramatic.
Father!
Hey, Pop.
Shawn, God...
What are you,
sleeping one off?
No.
I couldn't sleep last night,
my back's all out of whack.
Oh. God.
Hey, I hear they arrested
one of the forensics guys.
Yup. They grilled him
like panini.
He confessed
to the whole thing.
And the police found a fake
hospital badge at his apartment.
They think he was gonna
try to kill her last night.
How's the girl?
The doctors say
she's gonna pull through.
There he is!
Well, you're here, but you're not
gonna go out like that, are you?
Yeah, I can't make it tonight.
I gotta work a double.
Hey, I know. Why don't
you take Junior here?
I'll catch you next week.
What are
you talking about?
Didn't you just work back-to-back
shifts on that tennis thing?
Okay, fine. You got me.
All right. He's actually capable of
taking all the fun out of fishing.
He criticized my pole
technique for like three hours.
It's holding a pole in the
water. What is there to criticize?
Hey, ease up. That's my pop
you're talking about.
I'm beginning to understand
you a little better, Spencer.
Burton, you're back.
Sorry I missed
today's program, sir.
Well, it's okay.
I tried out
a new trust exercise
where I pull a rubber
band back as far as I can
and hold it up to my trust
partner's eye, and I say,
"Do you trust me?
Do you trust me?"
Wow. How did that go?
I wish my grip was better.
But the cornea
is resilient.
That's true, Tom,
I've heard that.
Now, Burton here hates to drag his
personal life into work matters,
but I feel like
you should know,
his dear grandmother somehow managed
to dislocate both of her shoulders, too.
I think it was the chin-ups she was
trying to do on the traction bar.
Burton,
you have missed almost every exercise
we had arranged for this weekend.
You left a work function to
tend to your ailing grandmother,
even if it was detrimental
to your career.
You know
what that tells me?
Tells me you really care
about people.
I do.
He does.
And after getting in touch
with my feelings this weekend,
I think that's exactly what the
Central Coast Pharmaceutical Company
is all about.
Yes.
Okay.
Burton's grandmother is gonna
need a little extra caring after.
He would never complain because
I know he loves his job,
but if there was any way that his
route could be a little less time...
Save your breath.
Burton, I know that everybody
here wants to get Dr. Magnotti,
why don't you swap him out for a
couple of your less-productive clients?
Oh, wow. Wow.
Thank you, Tom.
And my grandmother thanks
you, as a matter of fact.
Well, I'll tell you what.
Once she's feeling better,
I want you two to come on over to my
house and have dinner with my wife and I.
Oh, no, we
couldn't. We couldn't.
Lizzie makes a fondue
that'll knock your socks off.
Block of cheese about
the size of a house cat.
We're gonna melt it down
and gobble it up.
Okay.
All right.
Sure. We'd be honored. And
don't be such a stranger.
Hello, Tom. Hello!
I am so screwed.
Why?
He wants to meet
my grandmother. So?
So? You know that one of them is dead
and the other one lives in Jamaica.
Dude, relax. I know like five people
that could easily play your grandmother.
Okay, so you know
a line-dancing octogenarian
who can do chin-ups
and has two broken hips?
Yeah, as long as
she can be Chinese.
Just trust me.
Never mind.
Oh, you do trust me,
right?
I mean, I know it's a silly thing
to say after all these years,
but we don't have to do these
kinds of exercises, do we?
Battleship rematch?
No, that's all right.
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know