This isn't happening to me!
What is happening to you,
Shawn?
Only the worst thing ever!
A missing Captain Delicious
magic mood ring!
Dad, this is a crime.
Can you have them arrested?
First of all, Shawn, no,
this is not a crime.
Can't you just haul them in
for questioning?
Lay into them a little?
And who is "them"?
You know, the cereal people?
Oh, the cereal people, huh?
Well, I'll tell you what, Shawn,
you can spend a lot of time
calling 411 to get the number
for your cereal people,
they're gonna stick you
on hold forever,
listening to bad music.
Finally, you're gonna get
some dimwitted secretary,
who's gonna
take your message,
and then she's gonna
throw it in a waste bucket.
Or you can use the skills
I taught you
and you can outsmart them.
What am I missing?
Where is the ring?
Well, it'd be at the bottom.
Not in this box, you're right.
The big old bad cereal company
messed up.
So, you grab another box,
tough luck.
Where's the ring now?
At the bottom. Now I got
to eat the whole box.
And where's the ring now?
At the top!
That's right. You see, sometimes,
Shawn, you don't have to dig so deep.
All you gotta do is turn something
upside down to make it right side up.
And then...
you get your prize.
Thanks, Dad!
Explain to me again why we
couldn't sit in a restaurant
and eat
like civilized people.
Moving is good, Gus,
it helps the digestion.
Plus, you and I
never do this anymore.
What? Eat and jog?
No, talk. Just talk.
Check in with each other,
as men.
I wanna know
how you are.
how Gus is.
Really? Like you're
really asking me?
Yes, I'm really asking,
because I care.
Wow, okay.
Well, we've been working
cases nonstop for a month.
To be honest, I'm burnt.
I just want to take a nap.
I couldn't agree
with you more, buddy.
I think we should
lay low for a bit.
No more cases. Oh, I'm so
glad to hear you say that.
I was kind of worried
about telling you.
Don't be a silly goose.
Now, we've had a good talk,
I think we both felt it,
and look at this.
Here we are.
What is this, Shawn?
Okay, here's the thing.
The police may have
found a body,
which I may have picked up
on my police scanner,
which I may have
brought with me.
No cases, Shawn.
No cases. We go in, we see.
We say hello. And we leave.
Say hello? This is a crime scene.
You can't just walk in there.
McNab. Nabby!
Buzz.
Buzz? Seriously?
That's his first name.
Don't you ever talk to him?
Why would I talk
to anybody named Buzz?
Shawn! My man!
Pow!
Okay with... Yes.
You look trim.
Somebody made
their wedding weight.
Five more pounds. I'm close.
But I still have a month.
You'll get there.
You remember my partner?
Sure, yeah. Matt, right?
Gus.
Right.
So, what do you got going on up
there? Don't hold out on me now.
Looks like suicide.
A guy from the phone company
found the victim in his apartment.
Been up there
for a few days already.
Few days?
You mind if we head up, take
a look, poke around a little?
Oh, I don't know. Lassiter's
up there and he's in a mood.
Yeah, we just, uh,
got his coffee.
Wanted to bring it by,
make it right.
Oh, that's nice of you.
He asked me to get it,
but this is perfect.
Hey, did you just sip that?
You don't taste Lassiter's
coffee before you give it to him?
That surprises me, Buzz.
He's so particular.
No cream, no sugar...
It's three creams,
four sugars.
Yeah, it is.
Sharp as a tack.
You!
And fit!
We found a note.
The body's been here at
least three days. Maybe more.
All signs point to a 11-44.
Three 11-44s
in four months?
There must be something
in the water. Uh-huh.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
listen up. You know the procedure.
I want this done right.
I do not want any mistakes.
Hey, blowie,
I know you're new,
but next time if you want
to get your spit
all over the evidence,
why don't you
just lick it?
Clearly he doesn't need
any more coffee.
Okay, there is the dead guy.
Can we go now?
Relax. We just got here.
Have some mee krob.
How do you just eat when
there's a dead guy laying there?
What, is that rude?
Am I supposed to share?
Forensics.
Act natural.
That's it!
What? What do you see?
Red pepper flakes.
Is that a clue
or something?
No, it's a delicious spice,
and it's exactly what my mee
krob needs. I told you this.
What are you doing? This is a
crime scene. You can't touch stuff.
What?
Seriously, check this out.
A marinating steak?
What, you want
to eat that, too?
No, but don't you find
that a little odd?
That a man
would eat a steak?
No, that a man who was
ready to kill himself
would take the time to marinate
a steak for a future meal?
Dude,
this was not suicide.
This was murder.
The door latch
is still intact.
Now I ask you. If you
were gonna kill yourself,
wouldn't you want
the door to be locked
so that no one could barge
in on you right in the middle?
What? I don't...
What is it? I don't...
What in the name
of sweet justice
are you two doing
in my crime scene?
Your crime scene?
That's funny.
I didn't see your name
on it anywhere.
Get out.
We are.
Just thought you might wanna know
that this thing here, not a suicide.
Great.
Thanks for that. Really. And thanks also
for bringing a snack to the crime scene.
Oh, boy. Oh!
I'm sensing a...
I'm sensing
there was someone here.
Someone here in the room
with the victim when he died.
Someone with
a sliver of grease
on his or her shoe.
No, I'm not sensing
a struggle. No struggle.
The door.
Did you have to break down
the door when you got here?
No, it was open. Why?
No, no.
Don't encourage him.
Get up! McNab,
I want you to escort these
two men out of here now!
Come on, let me read the
witnesses. You know, due diligence.
Spencer, we did
the due diligence.
It was a suicide. There is no
crime. There are no witnesses.
You're wrong.
There is a witness.
There's a cat.
I wanna talk to that cat.
As soon as he's finished
licking himself.
Wow, I'm jealous.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I can't believe
you took that cat.
Gus, they were gonna ship him
off to an animal shelter.
What choice did I have?
Plus, this cat
is the lead witness
in a major murder
investigation. Wanna hold him?
Oh, no, you don't.
I'm not touching that cat.
You took the cat,
you carry it.
We are right on
this thing now.
I didn't have
anything substantial.
A steak, the chain on the
door, a stain on a carpet...
I wouldn't have believed me. We
needed an in. Now we have one.
Plus, he clearly likes you.
Give him a snuggle.
You know what?
I'm actually gonna enjoy this.
You having to carry
this cat around,
pretending you can
communicate with it.
I'm buying
a disposable camera
for when you have to clean
out its dirty litter box.
Let me tell you something.
This cat here is a gift.
A conduit for us
to save lives.
And he has more integrity
in his furry little hand...
Paw.
...than most people have
in their whole appendages.
Appendages.
What?
All of them.
Than most people have
in all of their appendages
combined.
Oh, yeah? I think he wants to
sleep on your chair. Isn't it cool?
How long are you
gonna keep this up for?
Until we solve the crime.
Don't you or your cat
get mad at me,
but I don't think
there was a crime.
Oh, really?
You don't think so?
No. Try telling that
to this poor little guy
who is traumatized seeing
his owner killed. Tell him.
I'm just saying
I can kind of get
where Lassiter is coming from.
A few suicides
is not uncommon.
Gus, did you look
at the sky today?
Blue, clear.
And did you feel it
out there? Warm. Nice.
Statistically,
people in mild climates
are far less likely
to kill themselves.
Now, if we were in
Vladivostok, we could talk.
Point is,
at the end of the day,
this was a 50-year-old man
living alone with a cat.
Do you want down?
You can get down.
You're probably right.
I know I'm right.
It was probably a suicide.
Thank you.
That was big of you to admit.
I'm just... I'm unclear
on one little thing.
What's that?
How do we explain the
second body they just found?
Deceased is in the car, over.
Detective O'Hara.
What, you're here
all by yourself?
Ah!
Damn it all.
Could have happened
to anybody.
Talk to me.
Well, victim is a female in
her late 20s, Gloria Starks.
We're waiting for forensics to
confirm, but appears to be a suicide.
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
Asphyxiation.
Oh, I'm afraid
the cat doesn't think so.
Turn around
and walk away.
This cat can tell us
if the killer has been here.
All I need is 30 seconds.
Watch this. You ready boy?
Huh? You ready?
What? What, over here?
Where? Wait.
That is... That is very
thoughtful. I'll tell him.
He says the fact that
you take three creams
and four sugars
in your coffee, dangerous.
Is that true?
Do you really take three
creams and four sugars?
So what?
Carly, that is a heart attack
waiting to happen.
You're still a young man.
That was amazing. How did you
do that? It was a lucky guess.
Don't you get tired
of saying that?
Now, with your permission,
I'd like the little boy cat
to sniff out the car.
Absolutely not.
Oops!
What did I just say?
Just relax and
let him do his job.
He might find something.
He's peeing.
No.
No, he's drawing your attention
to the evidence in the back seat.
By peeing on it. Nice.
Come here, kitty,
kitty, kitty.
Yes, did you make
good pee-pee?
Did you make
Yes, you did. What?
What. That's a...
That's a little inappropriate.
I'm sorry, that's rude.
He was just saying that he
would have done the same thing,
if he'd killed himself.
He would have swung by the dry
cleaners and grabbed the pantsuit first.
Maybe she picked up
the dry-cleaning days ago.
Did the cat
ever think of that?
What is he doing
right here?
He is measuring the amount
of carbon monoxide emitted.
Uh-huh. Okay. I knew that.
Yeah, you did.
Whoa!
Now, does she strike you as the
type that would go for heavy metal?
Any number of people could
have changed her radio station.
Now, Mr. Spencer, if you
and your new partner
are finished urinating on things,
I believe your work here is done.
Check out the dry-cleaning.
I'm on it.
Look, I don't care
what Lassiter says.
The cat is not my new partner,
Gus. Don't be ridiculous.
Then tell me again why the
cat gets to ride shotgun?
He gets carsick,
and you know this.
Do you want him to throw
up again back there?
Is that what you want?
It's not funny, Shawn.
Here, lay these down.
He's doing fine, aren't you?
This is a company car, Shawn.
That means I have to return it
in like-new condition.
Lay these down.
Whoa, whoa! Look at this!
What?
"Seventy percent off of storm
doors and window panes."
"Everything must go."
Gus, flip it over.
It's her.
"Struggling actress lands big
break in Santa Barbara play."
And then kills herself?
I don't think so.
Okay, you might be
onto something. Yeah.
The play is called
Dazzle and Stretch.
Dazzle and Stretch?
I was wondering if
I could ask you a question.
I could
really use some advice.
Yeah, all right.
Get on in here.
What can I do for you, McNab?
It's just that, well...
You're still married, right?
Are you trying to piss
me off? No, sir, no.
I just have a question.
On your wedding night
did you feel any,
well, any added pressure
to perform?
Excuse me?
It's just that my Francie
is going to be expecting a lot on
our first night as a married couple,
and I was wondering
if you had any tips for me.
What the hell kind
of sick bastard are you?
Thank you very much, sir.
I appreciate it.
So, what you are
trying to tell me is
now it's the cat that's
convinced these weren't suicides?
Yes.
Do you really think I'm going
to open a bunch of closed cases
just because
a cat tells me to?
This is it.
Yes, this is it.
The girl that was
found in her car,
Gloria Starks, she's here.
She's here with us.
Oh, despair!
I fear that you will leave me.
What choice do I have?
I dazzle
And I stretch
What the hell
is going on here?
Mr. Spencer,
this is telling me nothing.
He can't hear you right now 'cause,
see, he's channeling the cat
who's channeling Gloria.
I dazzle
Well, then
what are we looking at?
Bad acting.
I think she wants you
to see something in the paper.
Gloria's trying to
tell you something.
Dazzle and stretch
"Seventy percent off on
storm doors and window panes.
"Everything must go."
"Struggling actress lands big
break in Santa Barbara play."
- So what.
- So what?
Does that sound like a woman
who would kill herself?
Please,
all actresses are crazies.
I know, I dated one in college
once. She had a nose ring.
Good work, little buddy.
Whoa!
I don't know.
This is something. Something?
Oh, come on, you guys.
That's the biggest thing that
ever happened for that girl.
Now you need to stop waiting
around for another suicide
and start looking
for a serial killer.
Spencer,
get off my lap.
What does this mean?
I have no idea, but I've
seen it on Numb3rs all the time
and it seems
to work for them.
You ready to give up?
Four separate suicides, two of which
occurred before we came on the case,
and I don't see
a pattern of any kind.
Different ages,
different sexes.
Different
socio-economic levels.
Different methods of death.
No duplicate weapons,
locations.
Man, what have we got?
First we have a jumper, second, an oven,
third, pills, fourth, carbon monoxide.
They all have to be
connected somehow.
And what I see is
whole lot of nothing.
Nothing.
You see, sometimes, Shawn,
you don't have to dig so deep.
You just need to turn
things upside down
to make them right side up.
And there's your prize.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
Turning things upside down in
order to make them right side up.
And there's the prize.
This is the prize?
Going to the first dead
guy's place and what?
Talk to a dead guy?
No, we talk to
the dead guy's brother.
The dead guy's brother
lives at the dead guy's place?
They were roommates.
But that's the point.
He's getting rid
of the apartment.
And we're here to rent it.
We're what?
Why can't we for once
just talk to somebody as us?
Because, Gus, I don't
want him to be on guard.
If he thinks we're investigating
something, he'll clam up.
Wes Hiltonbock?
Yeah?
Hey, Shawn Spencer. I talked to you
on the phone about the apartment,
and this is Gus. It would
actually be for both of us.
Yeah, okay, come on.
Thanks, man.
Just so you guys know,
the utilities are included,
but I would require first and last
month and a sizable security deposit.
Oh, that's not a problem.
You take cats?
Yeah, I guess so.
You two guys have a cat?
We do, actually.
He's sort of like our child.
I see. How do you guys
know each other?
We're partners.
Got you.
Oh, no, no, no. No, it's fine.
Really, I'm totally fine.
No, we're partners in a
private... Relationship.
Believe it,
it's been a while.
We finish
each other's sentences.
So, tell me, Wes,
why would you want to give
up such a handsome apartment?
Do you...
Do you not like it anymore?
Ooh, Gus,
good news, shower for two.
Actually I just have some bad
memories here. I used to...
I used to live here with my
brother, but he passed away.
Oh, I'm sorry, man.
Was he sick, or...
He killed himself.
Oh, good Lord.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
Yeah, me, too.
We were real close,
you know.
God, was he depressed? I mean,
were there signs? Did you...
What am I... I'm sorry, you don't
have to answer those questions.
No.
Actually, I had no idea
anything was wrong, you know.
I mean,
he had so much to live for.
He was a great guy,
you know.
Smarter than me,
more talented.
He was a great singer.
He was really going places.
So look, are you guys... You
guys interested in the place or...
What do you think, honey?
I think it's great.
I think it's perfect.
All right, then. Well, I got another
couple coming by a little later so...
But I'll let you guys know
either way.
Shower for two?
That was so I could see
your face when I said it.
You know, you enjoy these
things more than you should.
I suffered through that for
no reason. We learned nothing.
Yes, but I grabbed this
while we were up there.
You took his mail?
It's not like I took his Sports
Illustrated. Dude, it's a phone bill.
You can't open someone else's mail,
Shawn. It's a federal offense.
Gus, he's dead.
So what?
Well, maybe I'll hold it to my
head and read it psychically.
Hurry up, Shawn.
Gus, who's gonna see us?
Hurry up.
Wait, there's like...
There's like 16 calls here
to some 1-800 stress line.
Including the last call
he made.
I've seen the ads for that.
So what?
A depressed guy
calls a stress line.
And I bet you a hungry guy
calls a pizza place.
That doesn't
tell us anything.
Yeah, but it might
give us a link.
I'm gonna run the other
victims' phone records.
With what? Your do-it-yourself
phone record running kit?
The next best thing.
The answer is in
the phone bills.
I need you to run
the victims' phone records.
What, no cat this time?
Julie, I'm very serious
about this.
I have a strong sense
about a stress line
and I know the link
is in the phone records.
I don't know why you would think I
would do something like this for you.
Some have said it's the hair.
Really? Who says that?
Oh, guess what? We already
ran the phone records
and checked out
the dry-cleaning.
Turns out the pantsuits were
picked up over a week ago.
What kind of dog and pony
show do you think we run here?
Gus, you wanna
take this one? No.
Let me put an end to this
non-case right now, okay?
Yes, all the victims
called the 1-800 stress line.
Not just once,
many times over.
Detective Lassiter and I
have combed everything.
We've gone to the bone on
these. All the way to the bone?
I know this is hard
for you to grasp,
but these people did have something
in common. They were troubled
and they were depressed,
and as sad as that is, they all
committed suicide. Case closed.
We've clearly
wasted your time.
It's not over, is it?
Of course not.
They all called the same help line and
they all killed themselves? Come on!
Shawn, that's what
stressed people do.
Strange how
he gave up so easily.
Yeah, it is.
Maybe we should take a closer
look at that stress line.
Gloria Starks
only called that line
'cause she was stressed
about an audition.
You call a help line and they find
you dead? That's not very helpful.
What if someone there is killing the
callers and making it look like suicide?
Gus, we go to the stress line,
I think we solve the case.
Come on.
Ta-da!
What is this?
You're looking at our
new business. Mazel tov.
Are you out of your mind? You
rented office space for this?
Gus, don't be a crazy
hooligan. I rented a sign.
Now, let's go say hello
to our new neighbors.
Hello, everyone!
Who wants pineapple?
Be honest.
Ah, you guys can slice it
up, fight over it later.
I'm sorry, gentlemen,
may I help you?
I'm Terrance,
I run the line here.
Terrance, hello.
I'm Shawn Spencer, this is my
partner Gus "Silly Pants" Jackson.
Just came by
to say hello.
We've opened up our own little
1-800 thingy down the hall.
Not as big as you guys.
More of a closet, really.
Your own 1-800 thingy, huh?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's called Dial-A-Psychic.
Maybe you recognize us.
I am the lead psychic for the
Santa Barbara police department.
McCallum murders.
Edmond robberies?
Over there, you? Nothing?
Nothing? Wow, really.
What, do you guys
live in this room?
So, you can know stuff about
me just by looking at me?
Yeah, pretty much.
Do it.
Do it?
Go ahead, show us.
Looking for a little demo.
Well, for one,
they don't like pineapple.
I don't know guys. I don't think Big
T wants us to take up any more...
Oh, no, no, no.
Go right ahead.
Half the lines are down, phones
are being worked on right now.
We have time for your
little trick. Oh, yeah?
Let's see what I
can come up with.
Loose flowing stanzas,
Bobby Frost.
Are you a poet, by chance?
Yeah! Yeah, I am!
Wow. How did you know that?
I guess you could say
I'm a bit of a psychic poet.
Oh, please, stop.
'Cause I'm like,
I'm freaking out here!
Do you see his eyeliner?
Guy could be the drummer
from The Cure.
Wow, I can see why you come out
here to eat. It's beautiful.
Sound of the seagulls, the smell
of the ocean, the salt air...
Hmm. I never noticed.
What do you got there?
What you asked for.
I ran the sheets on all the
volunteers at the stress line.
Do you mind?
It's police business.
Scram.
Let's see what we got here.
Well, lookie there.
It's a picture
of an old friend.
Hmm.
Hey, Rory.
Where the hell
have you been?
I've been sitting
on this mop bucket
in this tiny closet for the last hour
and a half waiting for you to show up.
I'm all cramped.
Well, get up, man.
Do some pushups or something.
I need you light and limber.
Do some pushups? Sure, like Clint
Eastwood in Escape from Alcatraz.
Sure, he spends the whole movie
in a tiny little cell, right?
But he's in the best shape
of his entire life.
Give me a little
piece of tape.
What happened to
the big ticking time clock?
Gus, what do you think
I've been doing all day?
My work happens here and here.
What are you doing?
I am trying to create a
pleasant work environment.
I can tell by looking at your
little area that you don't care.
We don't work here, Shawn.
We do until
we solve these murders.
But don't worry,
I have a plan.
You are gonna call the stress
line and pretend to be depressed.
No, I'm not.
Yes.
And I will go down the hall
when you make the call,
ask for Rory, so that
I can see him in action.
Why don't you call him?
Gus, please be serious
for one second.
No one's gonna believe
that I'm depressed. Come on.
I got an idea. Why don't you
have the cat make the call?
He's like your new partner,
right? Where is he, anyway?
Gus, he's far more comfortable
in your car.
Plus, I need him well rested for
when he identifies the killer.
Now, wait exactly two seconds
and then make the call.
Oh! I have no idea
what I'd even say.
Here's a good opener.
"Hello, my name's Gus.
"I have a deep-seated jealousy
for a tiny little boy cat."
Why would you put them
on speakerphone?
See, because I think
that tends to undercut...
Big T! Look sharp!
What is it now, Mr. Spencer?
Just wanted to pick
your brain for a second.
How many lines
you got going here?
I have 12 lines, but I'm
adding more all the time.
I get it, I get it, the more
lines, the more green, am I right?
I'm a non-profit operation.
The calls are free.
I'm not in this for the money.
Really, that's weird.
See, I'm thinking of
charging four bucks a minute.
Rory.
Rory!
Hey, Ror.
Hey. You really do
love your music, huh?
You kidding?
Music inspires me.
Yeah, you know, you don't
really strike me as the...
Charitable type? I was gonna
say sensitive, but sure.
Actually, I'm here as
part of a community service
on this assault beef,
you know.
I got into it with this guy
who didn't like my poetry.
So, 250 hours.
Two-fifty,
wow, that's intense.
Rory, that's Line 6!
I'll let you get
back to work. Sorry.
Hello, Stressline,
the extra S is for
extra stress. This is Rory.
Uh-huh.
Right, so you're experiencing
some stress.
Career and personal?
Well, yeah, I suppose.
I mean my career's not exactly
where I would like it to be.
No. No, I don't have
a girlfriend right now.
It's been awhile.
Right.
Right, that's not good.
Does it make you
have dark thoughts?
Like how dark are you talking?
Like, "wanna be dead" dark?
Okay, easy,
I just wanna say this,
like, right off the bat,
suicide is not the answer.
Who said anything
about suicide?
I just said maybe I should find a
new hobby, like coin collecting.
Or something
at the beach.
I like water activities.
Like drowning?
What? Drowning?
I don't want to drown!
No, no, of course you don't.
That's awful, okay?
But I don't care
what you say about
suicide in a lake
being poetic,
you know, like,
your body floating to the top
of the pristine, serene waters
and your final breaths
rippling out in
an ever-widening circle, you
know, like the circle of life.
But you have to stop
that kind of thinking.
You have so much to live for.
You're damn straight,
I have a lot to live for!
Of course you do.
You see, I can tell, this phone
call is helping you already.
Dude, what the hell was that?
Was he trying to help me? Cause I
feel really creeped out right now.
Dude, he put you
on the creepy train
headed for Creep Island where
the natives drink creep nectar
out of creepy coconut
shells... Shawn, it's horrible.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
He's nuts, Shawn.
Yes.
And worst of all,
he actually made
some good points!
I mean, pharmaceutical
sales, not sexy.
You are my only
non-work friend.
There's got to be
something wrong with that.
Hey, hey, hey,
what is this?
What?
Hang in there.
He's right, I need to start
taking some more risks.
Does that mean we can go
cliff diving in Zihuatanejo?
No. I'm being serious, Shawn!
Look, would it make you feel any
better if I told you Hiltonbock called?
We got the apartment! What
would make me feel better
is if we called the police!
This guy is dangerous, Shawn.
Let's call Vick.
Maybe get him arrested.
Gus, Gus!
What?
The only thing this guy is guilty
of right now is being a bad poet.
You know how this game works.
We cannot just pick up a phone and
beg the police to come and save us.
Look, just...
Just stay away
from the water for now.
Final decision, we wait.
No, it's this way.
You sure?
Yes.
Now, was that so hard?
Maybe you'd care
to explain this.
My eyeliner pencil?
So, you admit it's yours.
Funny how Gloria Starks'
suicide note
was scrawled across her
windshield in black eyeliner.
Yet no eyeliner was found
at the crime scene.
You, my friend,
are looking at exhibit A.
Bag it, O'Hara.
You like your music,
don't you, Rory?
Yeah, I do.
It's my inspiration.
I bet.
I bet it inspires you to kill.
That's why you
couldn't resist
playing your big-haired, drug-induced
death music on Mortimer Tilden's stereo
while you forced him
to swallow all those pills.
Or on Gloria Starks'
car radio
while she slipped into
unconsciousness.
And even now.
Let's have a little listen,
shall we?
What, you think you can
pull a fast one on me
switching out your head-thrashing
crap for this noise?
This crap is
all I listen to.
I hate metal music.
I use the details
that I get from callers
to write better poems.
I am not a killer!
Yeah, I know,
you're a poet,
but you're also an assaulter,
aren't you?
Who do you think arrested you
on that assault charge?
Oh, a guy from the phone
company found the victim.
I didn't kill anybody.
Get him out of my sight.
What?
You're not taking notes?
How could you
let him do that?
Now Lassiter gets credit for solving
the crime and we won't get paid.
Oh, we're gonna get paid.
How do you figure?
Lassiter didn't
solve the crime.
Rory is innocent.
He didn't do it.
He didn't?
No.
Then who did?
Just grip the spike with your
little foot and climb! Come on!
Why do I gotta go first?
'Cause you're a climbing machine,
Gus. Just, you know, be careful.
Grip the spike with your
foot! Okay, oh, okay, okay.
Grease.
Dude, dude! Dude,
I know who the killer is!
Can I come down then?
No, no, stay up there.
I have to figure out where
he's headed. Who is it?
Well, put it this way,
I don't think taking the
apartment is such a good idea,
unless you think it's cool
that our would-be landlord
is a serial killer.
Hiltonbock?
There was a pattern.
See, all the murders
coincide with dates
that Hiltonbock was
servicing the phone lines.
That's when he had access.
With this?
Yes. Yeah, yeah,
send that down.
Perfect!
See, this device stores all the
incoming and outgoing calls.
My guess is that wherever
number he dialed last,
that's where
Hiltonbock is headed.
And whoever that is,
is probably his next victim.
Hello, you've reached Buzz McNab.
I'm not in right now, but
please do leave a message
and I will get back to you
when I get in.
Oh, no.
Who are you calling?
Hello, Chief?
Hey, Shawn Spencer here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Look, I'm getting
a vibe right now as big as a Buick!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
no, you don't.
Stay, boy cat!
Hey, McNab,
so this is the place, huh?
It's nice. It's really nice.
Drop it!
Don't come any closer.
Put it down
or I will drop you!
I swear to God
I'm gonna shoot him.
Drop it! Everybody
breathe, just breathe!
Get out of here.
Well, the other ones must have
gone a lot smoother than this,
huh, Hiltonbock?
Though, comparatively,
it was probably pretty easy
to get Mortimer Tilden
to swallow those pills.
You wanna die, old man, huh?
Eat them!
Because you are not really
a cold-blooded serial killer.
Are you? No, but he threw his
own brother off a building!
I didn't push him
off the roof.
No, no, no. No, you didn't.
You didn't do that.
But you were there.
You saw it.
You saw the whole thing. You
saw him jump off the balcony
of the apartment that
you shared. He was weak.
There's a lot of weak people
out there, Hiltonbock.
Are you gonna track them all
down, huh, one at a time?
Punish them
for their weakness?
You wanna get back
at your brother so badly,
you don't even care
who these people were,
just that
they called the line.
And look, you're gonna kill
McNab here just because
he had a few
pre-wedding jitters.
I was just
looking for a little advice.
Nobody else would talk to me.
It's okay, Buzz.
We all have stress.
All of us.
Right here in this room.
I mean, take a good look,
Hiltonbock. We all have problems.
Who else deserves
to get shot or hung?
Maybe it's Gus.
That's enough, Spencer.
No. Shoot him.
What are you doing?
Yeah, maybe I should.
Don't listen to him.
He's a crazy person,
he's crazy.
That's right, I am crazy.
So maybe
you should shoot me.
Okay.
Here's the best part. It
doesn't matter what I think,
because you have a problem
that's a lot bigger than me.
This guy.
The man with his gun trained on
you is not only a fine human being,
with a strong Irish hairline,
he is an exemplary
public servant
and arguably the finest
detective mind
in the lower western
Santa Barbara County area
over the age of 35.
And right now,
while I'm speaking,
he is devising a swift
and stealth-like tactic
that is going to disarm you
and blow your freaking mind!
Anytime you're ready.
All right,
we gotta make the move.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
That was adequate, Spencer.
Don't thank me.
Thank the little boy cat.
There you are.
There's my big guy.
You are a hero.
You are a hero today. Yes.
Speaking of heroes, McNab,
I was gonna get you
something off
the registry online,
but it turns out the Chief already
got you the asparagus steamer.
So, instead I give you
this little guy.
Yeah.
If you take him in the car, he
likes to ride upfront, shotgun.
You know, there's
something beautiful
about the color
Fruity Puffs turns the milk.
I think it's the most beautiful
thing in the whole world.
You know, I've been thinking.
You're not the only one who
lives a charmed life, Shawn.
I got it pretty good, too.
Yes, you do, and it makes
me glad to hear you say so.
I mean,
the other day at work,
this dermatologist,
Katie Finestatt,
commented how I
looked handsome
carrying my sample case
into her office.
Finestatt said that?
Yes, she did.
And she is fine.
So, it got me thinking,
maybe pharmaceutical sales
can be sort of sexy.
There are times when I have
to stand a few feet away
because you're
literally sizzling.
You see what I'm saying?
I mean,
you may be my only non-work
friend, but you're my best friend.
And how many best friends
does one guy need, really?
That's my point.
It's all in the
attitude, Gus. Exactly.
Not sweating the small stuff.
Life is too short.
Too short.
Changing my attitude, Shawn.
Where the hell is my prize?
Where's my ring, Shawn?
Easy now.
No, no, I've timed the
bowls out perfectly, Shawn.
Me, then you, then me, then
you, then I get the prize!
What happened to "Not
sweating the small stuff?
"Life's too short,"
all that?
Did you open
the bottom of the box?
Now, why would I do
something like that?
That's my ring.
You know I would kill
for that ring, don't you?
Oh, you're upsetting me.
You just changed my mood from an
orangey yellow to a muddy brown.
You need to say
something sweet. Quick.
Gus!
That's so childish.
I'm gonna eat yours!
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know