[Electricity crackling]
♪ atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
[Oddly reverberating]
[Snaps fingers]
♪ atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
[woman screaming distantly]
♪ Julee Cruise's "Falling" playing ♪
♪♪♪
[Oddly reverberating]
[Soft clicking, scratching noise repeats]
[Soft clicking, scratching noise
continues]
It is.
I understand.
[Static crackling softly]
[Birds calling faintly]
[Engine rumbling]
[Joe] Hey, Doc.
Hey, Joe.
How's it going, Doc?
As good as ever.
[Box cutter slicing]
[Metallic clanking]
All right.
You gonna need any help, Doc?
Uh, heh, you know,
thanks, but no, thanks.
I like to work alone.
[Distant traffic whooshing]
[Distant horns honking]
♪ atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
[Atmospheric hum]
[Cameras humming softly]
[Atmospheric hum continues]
[Intercom alarm buzzes]
[woman over intercom]
Camera three.
[Computer processing softly]
[Buzzer sounds distantly]
[Elevator lift clicks, ascends]
[Atmospheric hum continues]
[Elevator lift clicks]
[Buzzer sounds distantly]
[Man over intercom]
Delivery.
[Keypad beeping]
[Keypad beeps]
[Lock rattles]
[Metal door slides open]
- Hey, Tracey.
- Hey.
You didn't have to bring it yourself.
Aren't you supposed to be working?
Oh, no, I-I got off at ten.
I brought two.
Can I join you?
Damn.
Tracey, I'm sorry,
but no one can come in here.
How much do I owe ya?
Oh, no, no, I‒
I got 'em for free.
I can't come in?
That's right.
Shoot. [Laughs softly]
Top secret.
Ooh.
Now I'm so curious.
You're driving me crazy.
[Sam] In fact, I got to go back in.
I'll stop by on my way in
tomorrow, if I can.
Okay, or if I miss you,
I can come back tomorrow night
and bring coffees, the same time.
Thanks, Tracey.
You can have 'em both.
[Keypad beeping]
You're a bad girl, Tracey.
Try me.
[Keypad beeps]
[Metal door slides open]
[Metal door slides shut]
[Metal door slams distantly]
[Elevator button clicks]
[Buzzer sounds twice]
[Soft warbling tone]
[Buzzer sounds distantly]
[Atmospheric hum]
[Computer processing softly]
[Swallows]
[Exhales]
Beverly,
tell Mrs. Houseman that we will
refund two nights of her stay
but not the whole week.
She and her New York friends
keep our spa running.
Oh, good.
How did the skunk get in her room?
What's that?
Uh, the‒the, uh, skunk,
how did it get into her room?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
It‒it wasn't even‒
even close to her room.
The skunk was on the whole
other side of the hotel.
- It was...
- [Jerry] I am here,
Brother Ben! [Stomping]
[Jerry chuckles]
- [Door opens]
- [Clears throat]
[Laughing softly]
Sweet and sour,
salty, crunchy... [Laughing]
Beverly,
my brother Jerry.
[Clears throat]
Hi. Nice to meet you.
So get back to Mrs., uh, Houseman
as we discussed...
Okay.
- ...and I'll get back to you later.
- Sure thing.
Is that the new girl?
Or should I say "woman"?
A woman like that, you can't call a girl.
Beverly, yes.
Are you banging her yet?
Oh, Jerry!
R-E-S-P-E-C-T.
Respect.
She's a beautiful soul.
And she's married.
That never stopped you before.
Sock it to me. Sock it to me.
Jerry.
What else do you have on your mind?
Swimming in my mind
at this time, literally,
is my new hydroponic indica-sativa hybrid,
a touch of the mythic AK-47
by way of the Amsterdam express.
It's baked into this banana bread
and infused in this potent spreadable jam
that's ideal for creative sojourns
of a solitary nature.
Wheels up.
[Crunches]
Jerry,
a prophet is without honor
who eats his own profits.
R&D, brother Ben.
It puts me in a groove,
and where it stops, nobody knows.
[Chuckles]
Thank God you are no longer
in the hotel business.
Where have you been, Ben?
Yeah, my new legally sanctioned business
is tripling our revenue.
Is that Mother's hat?
Hello. I'd like to see Sheriff Truman.
Which one?
Sheriff Truman isn't here?
Well, do you know which one?
It could make a difference.
Uh, no, ma'am.
One is sick,
and the other one is fishing.
Uh...
It could make a difference.
It's about insurance.
I'm not sure I will be able to help you.
I'd like to see Sheriff Truman.
I'll leave my card
and call in another day.
Thank you.
I'll keep the card,
but unless‒
♪ Muddy Magnolias'
"American Woman (Remix)" playing ♪
♪♪♪
♪ I know my worth ♪
♪ And who I am ♪
♪ Mister, if you're hard up ♪
♪ I could spare a few grand ♪
♪ Hell will freeze over ♪
♪ And I'll be damned ♪
♪ 'Fore I take orders ♪
♪ From any ol' man ♪
♪ Do I look like ♪
♪♪♪
Hey.
Where the hell do you think you're going?
[Grunts]
♪♪♪
Well, lookee here.
Otis.
[Chickens clucking distantly]
[Grunts]
[Shotgun clanks]
[Door creaks open]
Hello, Buella.
How you?
Buella,
Ray and Darya‒
have you got them
back there somewhere?
I'll get 'em.
And, Buella,
put something better at your front door.
It's a world of truck drivers.
[Buella] Ray!
Darya!
♪ soft atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
Ray,
Darya,
let's go.
Mr. C. Mr. C.
See ya, Otis.
♪♪♪
[Atmospheric hum]
[Buzzer sounds distantly]
[Elevator lift ascending]
[Metal door slides open]
Hey, Tracey.
He's not here.
- No one is here.
- [Metal door slides shut]
Really?
♪ soft brooding music ♪
♪♪♪
[Door closes]
Weird.
Where is he?
Does this, by any chance,
mean that I can
go in there with you?
I brought us two lattes again.
Well,
since there's no one here to stop you,
I guess you could come in
for a little while.
But I don't know how you're gonna get out
if the guard comes back.
Let's not overthink this opportunity.
[Metal door slides open]
[Atmospheric hum]
Whoa.
[Keypad beeping]
[Keypad beeps]
What is that thing?
A glass box.
[Laughs softly]
Yeah, but what's it for?
I really don't know.
[Sam] It's just a job I got
to help with school.
Whose place is this?
I heard a billionaire.
Some anonymous billionaire.
Mysterious.
[Atmospheric hum continues]
[Computer processing softly]
I'm supposed to watch the box
and see if anything appears inside.
What?
Do things appear?
I haven't seen anything since I started.
But the guy I replaced,
he saw something once.
What?
He wouldn't tell me.
Or couldn't tell me.
We're not supposed to say
anything about this place
or that glass box.
It's a lot of equipment.
[Tracey] Is it some sort
of science experiment
or something like that?
[Sam] I guess you could say that.
Do you want to sit down?
Okay.
Cozy.
Here's your coffee.
Thanks, Tracey.
[Tracey laughs softly]
[Atmospheric hum continues]
[Soft rumbling]
Do you want to make out a little?
What do you think?
[Tracey] Mm.
[Tracey] Mm!
[Soft rumbling]
[Atmospheric hum continues]
[Cameras humming softly]
[Tracey] Mm.
[Tracey moans softly]
[Very soft whooshing]
[Soft whooshing]
- Stop.
- [Gasps]
[Soft whooshing]
What?
Shh.
[whooshing]
- [Tracey whimpers softly]
- [Sam] Shh.
[Atmospheric whooshing]
[whooshing softly intensifies]
[Pounds glass]
[Screams]
♪ tense music ♪
♪♪♪
[Intense otherworldly whooshing]
[Glass shatters]
- [Intense whooshing]
- [Tracey screaming]
- [Flesh slicing]
- [Intense whooshing]
[Birds calling distantly]
What is it, Armstrong?
Oh, oh!
Ruth.
Ruth, are you in there?
Oh, oh, my goodness.
Come on. Come on, Armstrong.
Come on, Armstrong.
Come on.
Ugh.
Oh, come on, Armstrong. Come on.
Come on, little you.
Yeah. [Exhales]
By golly.
Oh, yes, hello?
Yeah, you don't know me.
This is‒this is Marjorie Green.
But my neighbor, there's something wrong.
Yeah, um, I haven't
seen her in three days.
Oh, and then there's that terrible smell.
And Armstrong smelled it in the‒
Then I smelled it‒
No.
No, Armstrong's my dog.
No‒
Oh, my address?
Oh, I-I-I don't know.
Um, oh, my goodness.
Um, yes, oh, I know this.
You know, I know this.
♪ atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
It was a funny thing.
I couldn't remember my address
when I called you on the phone.
Where's the smell coming from,
Mrs. Green?
[Gasps]
Oh.
Oh‒oh...
[Door creaks]
[Door shuts]
[Sniffs] Oh, there it is again.
There's that smell.
Ugh.
[Sniffing]
[Gasps]
Oh...
Ma'am, is there a manager
on-site with a key?
Oh, I don't know.
Um, Barney's usually here.
Um, do you want me to go check?
Yes, ma'am, if you don't mind.
Oh. I just remembered.
Barney's not here.
He's a funny one, that Barney.
He's in the hospital,
not the regular hospital.
Hey, uh, Darlene,
we're gonna need a locksmith
over at 1349 Arrowhead,
possible 10-54.
No, no, 1349.
Ma'am, who lives in this apartment?
That would be Ruth, Ruth Davenport.
And I just remembered something.
What's that, ma'am?
When Barney's out of town,
he leaves the keys with his brother.
And who would that be?
Oh, I don't know.
Um, I've never met him.
But Hank would know him.
Who's Hank?
Barney's friend, Hank Fillmore.
Where would we find Hank?
Oh, well...
I don't know right now.
He's our maintenance man.
But I saw him out back a little while ago.
Harvey?
Harvey, you son of a bitch!
Are you Hank?
What the hell?
Police, Mr. Fillmore.
We need your help.
Did Harvey send you?
Mr. Fillmore, we need a key
for Ruth Davenport's apartment.
We're trying to find Barney's brother.
Well, who told you
I was going to see Chip?
Who's Chip?
That's Barney's brother.
We need a key from Chip.
I was just on my way, but h‒
how did you know?
Well, do you have a phone number for Chip?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
[Laughs] Chip?
Chip ain't got no phone. [Laughs]
I'll wait for the locksmith.
[Marjorie] Excuse me.
Do you think that maybe
Ruth's out of town?
Why?
Well, it would be a shame
'cause I'm supposed to water her plants
when she's out of town.
I have the key.
Let's go.
Am I‒am I free to go?
Gentlemen, am‒am I free to go?
[Door creaks]
♪ atmospheric music ♪
♪♪♪
Uh-oh.
♪ brooding music ♪
Harvey, you son of a bitch.
Did you send the cops
to my place of business?
My work?
Harvey‒
Yes.
Yeah, I got it‒
I got all of it,
right here, but it's mine.
Mine and Chip's.
No. You opted out of this one, remember?
Harvey‒Harvey, don't‒
don't threaten me, Harvey.
Harvey.
Harvey?
[Camera shutter clicking]
[Muttering softly]
♪ soft brooding music ♪
♪♪♪
Constance?
[Chuckles softly]
Good for you, Dave.
You're behaving yourself for a change.
Want to help me with this?
Very carefully.
Keep it way up, off the body.
Uh-oh.
♪ dark music ♪
♪♪♪
[Exhales]
[Trees creaking]
[Line trilling]
[Lucy] Deputy Hawk,
Margaret Lanterman's on line one.
It's the line
with the light that's blinking.
Okay, Lucy, thank you.
[Button clicks]
Margaret, what can I do for you?
[Margaret] Hawk.
My log has a message for you.
Okay.
Something is missing,
and you have to find it.
It has to do with
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
Dale Cooper?
What is it?
The way you will find it...
...has something to do with your heritage.
This is the message from the log.
Okay, Margaret.
Thank you.
Good night, Hawk.
Good night, Margaret.
[Line clicks]
[Mouse clicks]
[Office phone ringing distantly]
Dave?
Dave!
[Dave] On my way.
You got to see this.
The head is definitely Ruth Davenport,
the woman who lived in the apartment.
And we've got a male John Doe.
We don't know whose body that is.
Nothing's come back on those prints.
But there's another set of prints
all over the apartment.
And we've got a hit,
a definite local hit.
[Dave] Bill Hastings?
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
He's my kid's principal.
[Constance exhales]
Dave!
- What are you‒
- Phyllis, is Bill home?
- Yeah.
- [Bill] Who is it, honey?
It's Dave, Dave Macklay.
Dave, hey.
What's going on, buddy?
Bill, uh,
I'm gonna have to put you under arrest.
- What?
- Please turn around.
I've got to cuff you,
and I've got to take you in.
Oh, my God, Bill!
- No, it...
- Oh, my God.
It's okay, honey. I hav‒
I haven't done anything wrong.
Could, uh‒could you tell me
what this is about?
We can talk about that at the station.
I want to come with you.
No, no, stay here.
There's been a mistake.
All right?
I haven't done anything wrong.
[Dave] You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
But the Morgans are coming for dinner!
[Dave] Do you understand
these rights I am‒
[Bill] I understand perfectly.
Just call George and tell him where I am!
[Car door opens]
[Car doors open]
[Car doors shut]
[Exhales]
She said something is missing
and it has to do with Agent Cooper.
But Agent Cooper is missing.
And he hasn't been seen or heard from
since before Wally was born,
and Wally's 24 years old.
He was born on the same day
as Marlon Brando.
[Lucy] Andy wanted to name him Marlon.
And we haven't even gotten
a Christmas card from Agent Cooper.
He hasn't even seen Wally.
Andy, Lucy, it's late.
Go down to storage
and get those files that we talked about.
Tomorrow morning, lay 'em all out.
I'll bring the coffee and the doughnuts.
Okay, Deputy Chief Hawk.
[Mike] Dave?
Don Harrison, State Police, Rapid City.
Hmm, are you taking this case?
It's yours, Dave.
Just here to help.
Mm.
Any luck with the missing body and head?
Nothing.
How long's he been in there?
About half an hour.
That's enough.
You sure you don't want to take this?
Mike said you're fishing buddies.
I've known him since high school.
He might tell you more than he'd tell me.
Go on in.
[Dave] Oh, I'm sorry about the delay.
Uh, did they get you some coffee?
[Bill] I'm good with the water.
Can you‒can you, uh,
uh...
can you please tell me what's going on?
We'll get to that,
but I have a few questions
that I have to ask you first.
Um...
Do you know a Ruth Davenport?
[Tsks]
That name sounds familiar.
Uh...
the librarian?
- Yes.
- Ah, okay.
That's her.
Do you know her?
Not really.
We say hello to each other.
Mm.
When did you see her last?
Oh, I don't know.
Uh, let me think.
Maybe a couple months ago?
Mm.
Have you ever been
to Ruth Davenport's home?
No. I've never been there.
I don't‒I don't‒I don't
even know where she lives.
Mm-hmm.
Have you ever been
to the apartment building
at 1349 Arrowhead Road?
No.
I never have.
[Clears throat] Uh,
I-I‒I've‒I've never‒
I've never been there.
Could‒could you please tell me
what this is about?
Did you get the warrant?
Any minute.
Judge was up the mountain.
[Dave] Bill,
can you account for your time
over the last three or four days?
Sure, yes, I can.
Uh, I've been at school every weekday.
[Dave] And evenings?
Our high-school principal.
[Bill] Uh, Wednesday,
I went home right after school.
Thursday, we had
a-a meeting in the evening.
And then...
[Pen scratching]
...I went home.
And then...
uh, Friday, I went‒
I went out to dinner, Phyllis and I.
But we went home right after that.
And‒and I was home all day today.
What‒what‒
what was this Thursday meeting about?
Curriculum.
F-faculty evaluation.
It's a bimonthly meeting.
Mm-hmm. And when did it end?
[Sucks teeth]
Around 9:30, I believe.
I don't know. We ordered pizza.
[Pen scratching]
And...
you went home directly after?
Yes.
And what time did you get there?
10:15, 10:20.
Well, how long does it take you
to drive home usually?
Um...
Oh, yeah‒
oh, yeah, now I remember.
I gave...
♪ soft brooding music ♪
...my assistant, Betty, a ride home.
♪♪♪
Something wrong with her...
car, something wrong...
[Pen scratching]
♪♪♪
I think I'd like to speak to George.
He's my lawyer.
Is‒is‒is‒is he‒is he‒is he here?
I can check.
But, Bill, is there anything else
that you would like to tell me
before we get the lawyer involved?
Please tell me what's going on.
[Pen clicks]
Ruth Davenport was murdered.
And your prints are
all over her apartment.
What?
[Exhales]
[Don] Show Mr. Hastings to his new room.
He can meet with his lawyer there.
Right, you're gonna have
to come with me now, Bill.
Right out here.
[Dave] To the left here, Bill.
[Door creaks, shuts]
Right‒right here, Bill.
Dave,
could I speak to Phyllis?
Could you let me‒
could you let me do that?
[Sighs]
I'll see what I can do.
[Lock clatters]
[Exhales]
[Shoe squeaks]
[Metal door slams shut]
Mrs. Hastings,
we have a warrant
to search your house.
This is unbelievable.
We have guests for dinner tonight.
Is that Bill's car
in the driveway, ma'am?
It's the Volvo.
We'll need the keys.
Dave?
It has to be done, Phyllis.
[Sighs]
[Keys scrape, jingle]
We're coming in.
Let's go.
[Flashlight clicks]
My flashlight's broke.
♪ soft brooding music ♪
♪♪♪
Woof.
[Soft clicking, scratching noise repeats]
[Soft clicking, scratching noise
continues]
[Electricity crackling]