Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Egg, egg, baby.
We're going coast to coast
for a full hour of breakfast.
This is kind of, like,
wine-tasting for me.
I'm gonna cleanse my palette
between bacon.
We've got waffles in Phoenix...
That's a hot Frisbee of fun.
...old-school diner favorites
from Buffalo...
You know, like,
a side of ham with some ham.
...to Salt Lake City...
The biscuit-baking bad boy.
...and a joint
in Long Beach, California,
throwing everything
into one crazy concoction.
I see why they call it the mess.
Plus, a Cajun classic
in Louisiana...
That sauce
is gonna be out of bounds.
...a killer combination
in Los Angeles...
Bacon donut.
...and in Jersey...
Coffee.
...the best looking pancake
I've ever seen.
That is crazy.
So wake up
and smell the huevos...
"Huevos" meaning the eggs.
...for this
top-of-the-morning mash-up.
You could convert
non-breakfasters.
That's why we're here.
Non-breakfasters?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
-- Captions by VITAC --
Closed Captions provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC.
When you're
in downtown Phoenix, Arizona,
you just got to check out
this little joint
called Matt's Big Breakfast.
Now this dude digs breakfast
so much,
he devoted
an entire restaurant to it.
I just got to meet this cat,
Matt.
Who's having
the breakfast special today?
It's so good.
Eggs and pork chop.
It was very good.
The atmosphere is
tiny and squished and compact.
That's what's great
about it.
Chris, party of one.
It's the best breakfast in town,
hands-down.
It feels more like
you're eating breakfast at home.
Is my mom here?
I would say
the specialty is quality.
It's breakfast basics
done the right way...
It's squeezed
a lot of oranges.
...totally from scratch...
Breakfast isn't really
complicated. Keep it fresh.
...made
with the best ingredients.
We don't even own a freezer.
We don't own a microwave.
There's no microwave
and no freezer in this joint?
No microwave, no freezer. No.
Waffle?
Thank you.
Waffle's perfect.
They're really light,
very delicate.
'Cause making them
Matt Pool's way
means making fresh batter
three times a day.
You want to help me crack,
or should I just do it all?
Well, I've never cracked
in tandem before.
And jazz hands.
We've got two cups
of sugar here.
We're gonna put some butter
in there -- put it in melted.
Now, you're not worried about
kind of poaching those eggs
a little bit
with that hot butter?
We'd worry
if I didn't start whisking.
Okay.
The flour
and the whole milk,
I'm gonna add them
in alternate doses here.
Careful.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
We do have a mixer here,
right?
No, no,
we don't have any mixer.
There's no room
for a mixer.
Then we add the baking powder
with just a teaspoon of salt.
Looks like cake batter.
That's it right there.
Put that down,
give it a flip.
And it only takes about a minute
so you flip it back over.
It's like a hiking boot
just walked on a pancake.
Look at that thing.
That's a hot Frisbee
of fun.
Syrup.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Granny's kettle on the flat-top
all day is actually hot syrup?
It's hot syrup ready to go.
You don't want to put cold syrup
on a hot waffle.
That'd kind of ruin it.
It's got a really nice crust
to it.
Look at it inside there.
You see how nice and light
and airy?
Really good. I'd eat that waffle
again in a heartbeat.
I got to tell you, man.
You could convert
non-breakfasters.
That's why we're here.
Non-breakfasters?
Actually...
Home fries,
hash browns.
...he already has.
Now, what will the wait
turn into,
like, on an average weekday
or a weekend?
- Hour and a half.
- To get in?
Oh, yeah, and it's worth
the wait, for sure.
I'm gonna take Gregory,
party of two, please.
What do you like
about it here?
Hmm, my daddy owns it.
I still remember, you know,
going to a little coffee shop.
My dad loved coffee shops.
He always sat
at the counter.
I just figured there were people
here that would appreciate
just kind of old-fashioned
mom-and-pop-run restaurant.
So three years ago,
he and his wife, Arenia...
Hi, how are you?
...got a counter
of their own.
I'm here almost every other day.
It filled up quick.
Welcome to Phoenix.
How are you, Mayor?
Enjoy the same thing
each time you come in?
No.
I like the waffles
or the omelettes --
The waffles
with the real maple syrup.
And it's that real thing
that's keeping this joint
packed.
Every piece of my breakfast
is so good.
We get all of our pork from
a little local butcher shop.
They don't deliver,
and I pay retail.
It's the craziest thing
in the world.
And once you have
the bacon here,
you'll never eat bacon
anywhere else your whole life.
This is kind of like
wine-tasting for me.
I'm gonna cleanse my palette
between bacon.
It's as thick
as a ham steak.
Great texture to it.
Whole grain bread.
You know that they
make this stuff sliced?
I don't like
the uniformity of bread.
The man has an issue
with uniformity of bread.
And then we serve it
with a little bit
of a homemade local preserve.
Mm.
Oh.
It's like
an open-faced jelly donut.
Most of it's
all the way out here.
There you go.
And Matt's putting fresh
rosemary in his home fries...
Kind of melt
in your mouth.
...cooked in tons of butter,
just like the hash browns.
Butter the grill.
We lay out the hash browns.
We butter it on top, and then
we just keep flipping them.
Oh, those are killer.
He's even making fresh pesto
for his breakfast pork chops.
We make
a pesto marinade.
We put the garlic
in there first.
It's about 1 1/2 ounces
of fresh basil, pine nuts.
Made a red bell pepper pesto
with macadamia nuts.
For a pasta or for...
Oh, no,
just put it facial.
And I'll wear it
as a mud mask at night.
That's good.
That's a secret. Great.
Some salt, pepper,
and then extra virgin olive oil.
And you just
kind of do this by sight.
Look at the color
in that.
I've got some chops here.
Toss them around.
Can I lick the bowl, Mom?
It's all yours.
Money.
How long
does it marinate?
At least three hours or so.
It's gonna get
a nice, little crust on it.
Looks like
it's time to flip.
Those bad boys
got to be done.
You want to give them
a shot?
You can just see the juice
coming out of it.
Oh, fantastic.
You know,
you get the little pesto,
get some of the bite
of the garlic.
I love that you do
fresh cracked pepper.
That's my biggest thing.
The food
has a lot of love in it.
And you can always taste it
when people cook with love.
The special is, today,
corned beef hash
with poached eggs.
Thank you.
Welcome.
I want it to be like
a Midwestern-style diner.
Window, please.
Thankfully, people recognize it.
Well, the food's always great.
You can tell that whoever
made this food is an artist.
They're the sweetest people.
Just make you feel like
you're part of the family.
Well, I appreciate it.
Thanks for coming in.
So, on our next stop
for "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives,"
where do you want to go?
Help!
Well, how about
Buffalo, New York...
Dig it.
...to a classic diner dishing
out a true labor of love?
And this is all
for a breakfast item.
One item.
And in Dania Beach, Florida...
The party's getting started,
man.
...scratch-made pancakes
mixed to perfection.
Full steam ahead, Captain.
Aye.
So, here I am --
Buffalo, New York.
I'm about five miles
northeast of Lake Erie
at a joint that was once a diner
and then changed
into a Chinese restaurant,
well, then transplanted
from Pennsylvania
and then turned back
into a diner.
And guess what? That's not even
the amazing part.
These guys are --
they're curing their own ham,
They're corning their own beef,
and they're smoking
their own bacon.
This is Lake Effect Diner.
Pulled pork.
The real deal.
Barbecue meatloaf.
An upscale version
of the old classic.
Blueberry pancakes.
You can really taste
the difference.
Are there
a lot of diners in Buffalo?
Not too many.
Not like this.
- A '50's legacy...
- Two sunshines in a glass.
...that Tucker Curtin...
Italian sausage.
...and his wife, Erin,
brought back to life.
Table 24.
We went looking
for the diner car.
And we were able
to resurrect it
and put it back
into service again.
Now, this joint is smoking --
for real.
Ready to rock and roll.
Everything
from turkey to bacon...
Oh, it's so good.
...to ham.
So a boneless pork leg.
And you're gonna make
your own --
We're gonna make
our own ham.
We'll start with our brine,
okay?
About a gallon of water,
some dried cloves here,
black peppercorns.
Dried mustard.
Lots of dried mustard.
Light brown sugar made right
here in Buffalo, New York.
Maple syrup.
Attaboy.
Sodium nitrate here.
Ah, for some nice color.
And then kosher salt.
Okay.
Bring that
to a little simmer.
Yeah, so we're gonna get that
into a rumbling boil.
And then,
we'll cut our ham in half,
pour the cooled brine
on top.
And that's
a 12 to 14-day process.
And then
it'll go to the smoker.
For about three hours.
We'll also slow-smoke
the bones that we'll use
in the stock
for our red-eye gravy --
Smoke those
over mesquite charcoal.
And we also burn
apple and hickory woods.
Wow.
Sugars are starting
to caramelize up on them.
Look at this.
Just take a little looky-loo
at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
It's got
that real maple --
Don't talk in the middle of it.
And this is all
for a breakfast item on a menu.
Correct.
A breakfast item.
One item.
So now we take them,
pop them in the oven,
bringing them up
to about 145.
Finish the cooking process,
take them out.
We got our bones.
They're all smoked off.
It got the fat
nicely out of them.
Now I'm gonna dump
the pan juices in there.
Little mirepoix.
Carrot, celery, and onion.
Dig it.
Black peppercorn.
We are going to be
straining this?
Yes, we are.
Some kosher salt.
Frank's hot sauce.
Wow.
This is the secret
to good wings.
It's also the secret
to good red-eye gravy.
Brindle of fresh thyme.
Add some coffee to it.
Now, how long will this
sit there and simmer?
For about three hours.
Strain it and it'll be ready
to serve with the ham.
Correct.
Got our ham right here.
Slice him up.
Get that going on the flat-top
with eggs and home fries.
Egg, egg, baby.
A little bit
of our red-eye gravy here.
Let me get these eggs,
some of our home fries.
Get our ham
on there too.
A little more
red-eye gravy.
I kind of hoped
you were gonna say that.
Mmm.
this is very flavorful.
Tender ham, for sure.
You know, like, a side of ham
with some ham.
Being raised
eating red-eye gravy,
I've seen a lot
of different variations.
I do think I would like to have
a cup of red-eye gravy to chug.
Mmm. Awesome, bud.
Nice job.
Order up.
Ham, red-eye gravy.
Very good, very moist.
Everything is really fresh,
really homemade.
95% of the things
you guys serve,
you make from scratch.
Absolutely.
Order up.
Our customers
deserve the best.
If we have the ability
to provide that quality food,
it's our job to do it.
Classic diner feel,
but it tastes more like
a home-cooked meal.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
And you're still doing it
with smiles on your faces.
And you're still married.
We are.
On "Triple D,"
when we visit a place,
it's got to have
three things going --
the people and their story,
the food, and the location.
Today, we're at Grampa's,
where it started out
as a bakery.
Their comfort food is righteous,
and, hey, it's in Florida.
Fresh rugelach --
chocolate and raspberry.
Just like home cooking.
Happy food.
Way to a man's heart
is through his stomach, right?
Pancakes
in the middle of the day?
Pancakes any time
of the day.
If it's comfort food...
Pork loin, mashed potatoes.
...they're doing it here.
I remember
when it was just
a small little bakery place
in the early '70s.
Started by Grampa himself.
Ronnie Grampa.
Now, Grampa's your last name?
Yes, sir.
Your dad's dad,
Did you call him Grandpa Grampa?
That's a good one.
26 years ago,
Ronnie brought general manager
Tommy Grimes aboard.
They're fresh
shadow cakes.
Together, they expanded
the place near Fort Lauderdale,
into a full-fledged restaurant.
We tried to follow
the pattern of the bakery
into the restaurant
to give people
the same kind of stuff.
- The same feeling, yeah.
- Order up.
Do you need anything else
at this time?
No, this is great.
It's always good.
It's always fresh.
I don't have to do it at home.
And who's doing
scratch pancakes at home anyway?
These are what
my mom would make.
They're delicious.
And whose recipe
was this?
Me.
Pastry flour.
Lot of elasticity.
Exactly.
- Okay.
- 24 ounces of sugar.
Full steam ahead,
Captain. Aye.
I learned that
on the ship.
We're gonna add buttermilk.
We don't want
to add all the liquid
until we get the lumps out.
Clear.
Halfway around.
Fire in the hole.
Oh, stop.
This is one
of the most important
tools of the trade --
the scraper.
Let's go third speed.
Fire in the hole.
Go around
one more time, sir.
On two or three?
Three this time.
Oops, four.
Nope.
No.
48 eggs.
One quart of fresh milk.
You meet people that are excited
about things they're doing.
Tell me about
3 pounds of melted butter.
This is 3 pounds
of melted butter.
The party's getting
started, man.
Baking powder, baking soda.
Two ounces of salt.
That's a pretty elaborate
pancake mix.
Better be good.
It's gonna be.
Don't worry.
I'm not.
You're the pancake master.
And nothing down
on there, huh?
Nothing down.
It's got butter in it.
You never pat them
and you never --
No, you don't mess
with them.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Mary Lou Retton.
Some people like a chunk
of butter, you know what I mean?
A chunk of butter.
Look at that --
nice layers and the holes.
It's really light
but texturey.
Good pancake, man.
Grampa's makes the best pancakes
in South Florida.
Fluffy and perfect.
That was
a lot of work, too.
Got to give them something good
or else they won't come back.
Oh, they're coming back.
I'm here
morning, noon, and night.
It's really good.
This is the place to go.
And thanks for coming in.
Coming up...
I like it.
...in Minneapolis, Minnesota...
We're sort of a dump
aspiring to be a dive.
...a serious
morning wake-up call.
I need
another hollandaise.
And in Mandeville, Louisiana...
I'm a
grit-eating fool.
...A New Orleans favorite
I just can't get enough of.
Don't hold back on me.
Matter of fact,
just fill that up.
One of the best things
about classic American diners,
drive-ins and dives
is you really can't judge a book
by its cover,
like this breakfast joint
in Minneapolis.
Would you believe
a James Beard Award winner?
This is a dive.
Everybody else,
move all the way down.
I got a waffle up.
- There's a waffle up.
- It's not split.
Don't send it down
until it's split.
Don't send it back.
Let them split it
themselves.
You really consider
this place a dive?
Of course.
Look at it, for crying out loud.
And owner Doug Grina's doing
all he can to keep it that way.
I need
another hollandaise.
No, you don't.
But then there's the food.
Best breakfast in town.
Everything's made fresh
and to order.
We make our own
corned beef hash.
I love corned beef hash.
You want that?
That's a good-looking hash.
Wow.
That hash is money,
man.
Thank you.
What's in it?
Onions, garlic,
green pepper, parsley,
just a tiny hint
of horseradish.
This might be a dive,
but you really make --
I love food.
I go home from here.
I stop
at the grocery store,
see what looks good,
and plan a dinner.
And as for
that dive thing...
We're sort of a dump
aspiring to be a dive.
...maybe, but in 2004,
this place actually received
a James Beard Award
as an American classic.
I haven't worn this since
I tried to go through security.
You know, the James Beard Award,
that does help the --
From the dump to the dive,
that's a help.
And this is
your business partner?
Yes, that's my partner,
James Brandes.
Look at you guys.
You guys look like
a couple Hollywood producers.
And it all started
with the commitment
to make everything ourselves,
which started with Al.
And we continued.
So, who was Al?
Al's a terrific gentleman
who started this place in 1950.
He retired in '74.
Doug's been here since '79.
And the setup hasn't changed
in years -- grill up-front...
Got half an eggs benny
and a whosy and a what.
...omelettes and scrambles
in back by the water heater.
I need a three-egg huevos
on an oval.
You need what?
Three-egg huevos
on an oval.
I'm gonna get you
at Radioshack --
$20, intercom system.
Money.
What do I need
that for?
And somehow, they really do
turn out some great food.
Tell me about the José.
The José was named after a guy
who used to eat in here.
His name was George?
His name was José.
Get out.
No, I'm not kidding you.
What's in a José?
Two poached eggs, salsa,
and cheddar cheese.
Put down two hash browns.
Pour some oil
on them.
On the potatoes.
Yeah, nothing like
a little cholesterol.
That's not cholesterol.
That's soybean oil.
There you go.
I blew that.
No, no,
this is a beauty.
This is where
the magic happens.
This is the magic,
see?
They don't know
this part.
Yeah, not that the guys
are right behind us.
But that doesn't matter.
I know.
Okay,
then the cheddar cheese.
Look at that!
You know how much this costs?
It's $12 each.
No,
get out of here.
Come on, dude.
I mean, $5.25?
Yeah.
Get $7, $8 out of these two.
Price just went up.
They're students.
Doug says he doesn't like
to raise prices.
Of course, he doesn't like
to paint the place, either.
Or throw anything out.
Or change much of anything.
No credit cards here.
Instead,
they've got payment books.
Books back
from the '60s.
Here's how it works --
You put some cash
on your account.
Hey, Doug.
You take checks?
Yeah, even bad ones.
Says here you started
with 41. 33 from your old book.
And they keep track
as you eat backwards to zero.
You eat the same thing
every time, don't you?
'Cause it's $4.81, $4.81.
Oh, here's Maggie
with some friends -- 19.50.
That's okay?
That's okay, yeah.
Cool if I put my breakfast
on here?
Oh, yeah.
Where else
do you eat breakfast?
This is the only place.
How about you?
Actually, yeah,
the only place.
I make it at home,
or I come here.
To a dive...
Everybody else
move all the way down.
Covered over a former alley
between two other buildings...
Some
of the short blues...
...where the crowd backs up
waiting for a seat...
I got a stack
and sausage up.
and a self-trained cook
keeps the tradition alive,
at least until closing time.
What time are you guys
gonna close today?
1:00 P.M.
Somebody pick up
these pancakes.
So here I am
at beautiful Mandeville
on the north shore
of Lake Pontchartrain,
Just a quick 25-mile jog across
the causeway from New Orleans,
to check out
a joint that's got a name
that's as unique
as the chef who owns it.
This is
Louie and The Redhead Lady.
I can dance.
And this is Louie.
Here we go.
Voodoo Benedict.
Charles, how you doing?
And this is the redhead lady...
So he has his
own special pancakes.
Love Ginger and Louie.
...New Orleans natives
Chef Louie Finnan...
Coming around.
...and his wife Ginger.
Okay. I will.
You know he's back there
slaving in the kitchen.
The owners really make it,
as well as the food
and the flavors.
Red beans and rice.
But this is
real-deal Louisiana.
Yes, this is good as it gets.
I've been
in the restaurant business
for almost 40 years.
And he starts serving
Louisiana favorites
bright and early.
This is our breakfast place,
and Louie fixes us
whatever we want.
Banana foster pancakes.
Come here on Sundays.
It's the best breakfast.
I've got a Grillades and Grits.
Grits and Grillades, it's
actually a real patty and grits.
It's a typical
Louisiana breakfast.
It's comfort food,
and it's wonderful.
I'm a grit-eating fool.
We're starting with grits.
A little water,
butter, salt.
Do you bring the water to
a simmer and then add the grits?
Yes.
So we let these work.
And now, we're gonna start
working on the veal.
So just a nice little
tenderizing.
Then what he said...
All day long,
if you want some more.
Okay, let's do a little flour,
a little black pepper.
Precise measurement.
Exactly.
Italian dressing mix,
salt.
You know, in New Orleans,
you never leave anything alone.
That's right.
We've got to season
everything.
So, there's
our little dredge.
Little butter-flavored oil.
To the black iron skillet,
put a little seasoning.
Steak seasoning?
Yes.
Now, we're gonna start
our sauce.
A little
buttery-flavored oil.
some julienne onions.
Okay, thin-sliced,
white onion.
Yes, sir.
Now, we're gonna add
a little bit of --
Beef stock
that you make in house.
Let that sit there
and cook down with those onions
so it reduces
real nice.
Garlic.
See, I ain't afraid
of the garlic.
Don't be.
Pickled pepper salt.
Oh, I love pickled pepper --
kind of
a vinegary steak sauce.
A little Sherry.
So, a real nice,
traditional,
old steak sauce
we're making here.
Absolutely.
Now, make a little roux
to thicken it --
some flour
and some melted butter.
Whisk that.
Sticks right on there.
That sauce is gonna be
out of bounds.
Putting the veal
into the grillade gravy.
Now, we're gonna start to absorb
some of that great au-jus
into the crust
of the veal cutlet.
Right.
Nice, tight grits.
Yes, sir.
Don't hold back.
Oh, you want some more?
Don't hold back on me.
Matter of fact,
just fill that up.
What?
We're talking huge flavor --
huge flavor.
This is a breakfast
that eats like a dinner.
Oh, I don't even
want to talk about it.
Grits and grillades.
One of my favorite dishes.
The veal is nice and tender.
Wonderful sauce.
It hits the spot every time.
Brother, I got
to tell you something.
This is an experience
and then some.
You got to come meet
this guy.
It is off...
The hook.
Hey!
Up next on this
full hour of breakfast...
Mmm.
...in Salt Lake City, Utah...
You've only made close
to 3 million biscuits.
...I'm throwing down
a culinary challenge.
I could blindfold you,
and you could make this.
Yes.
We got to do this.
And in
Barnegat Light, New Jersey...
No spill. No spill.
Fantastic dismount.
The crowd goes wild.
...a chef cooking to the beat
of his own drum.
That's money.
You know, we find a lot of
great places here on "Triple D"
'cause one person e-mailed us
and told us to check it out --
or maybe two or three people.
And then,
you get a place like this --
right outside of Salt Lake City,
a 79-year-old diner
called Ruth's.
Now this is
such a local legend,
it seems like we heard
from everybody.
Who sent me the e-mail
about coming to Ruth's?
All of you hit send
that the same time?
Who was first?
Why'd you send me
the e-mail?
Because it's a fabulous place.
Where are you gonna find
this kind of history?
With all kinds
of diner classics.
I have meatloaf,
chicken-fried steak.
I moved out here
to go to college in '95.
Biscuits were good then.
They're just as good today.
Just like the place itself,
a local favorite since 1930.
Ready to plate it.
And owners
Erik and Tracy Nelson
are making sure that when
folks come to Ruth's...
Can I get your name?
...they get
what they expect.
Biscuit gravy.
Biscuits and gravy.
Hey, sign me up.
Tastes better
than my mom used to make.
They make them every day.
Actually, just one guy --
baker Inez Monreal,
cranking out thousands a week.
How many years
you worked here?
About 16.
You've only made close
to 3 million biscuits.
The biscuit-baking
bad boy.
What do you think
of that name?
All right,
so how do we make a biscuit?
We'll start
with margarine first.
You've got some flour
from here.
Wrong day to wear black.
Baking powder.
About that much.
About that much,
and about that much?
Just 'cause you made
3 million --
3 million biscuits,
I can measure by hand.
Add some salt,
and sugar, eggs.
That's a lot of eggs.
And buttermilk.
Water.
On slow,
And you stop it.
That's it?
Now, we can add
more water.
Okay, you just got to do it
by feel.
So let me ask you this --
Do you think
I could blindfold you
and you could make this?
Yes.
We got to do this.
There you go.
Ready.
Okay, get started.
He's got the margarine.
He knows
where his bins are.
It's not bad.
He found the salt.
Now we're gonna
get sugar.
He's picking up speed
as he goes.
Now we'll put the eggs...
There we go.
...with the buttermilk.
Water.
This is amazing.
And we'll just let it mix.
I made it.
You are the blindfolded,
biscuit-baking bad boy,
right here.
Yeah.
A little bit more flour
on top.
So you can work with it.
You get
your biscuit cutter.
Oh, we're doing it now.
It's okay.
Don't be afraid.
You do each one of them
like this?
Just like that.
He's like a machine.
There's got to be
a secret button.
So these go
in the oven now?
300 degrees, 35, 40 minutes
till they get a nice brown
on top.
We gonna make
some of our gravy.
We start with the oil,
diced onions, garlic,
pork sausage.
So we got it
cooked down --
Like that's not gonna be
great gravy.
We add the black pepper,
salt, dry basil.
And then we just sautéed them
a little bit.
And then a little flour
to make the roux.
Heavy cream and milk.
Let it sit there and simmer
for a little bit.
A little hot sauce --
That's what I'm talking about.
There's your
biscuits and gravy.
Wow.
It's like
mound o' biscuit.
Mmm.
That's great.
The biscuits
are really nice and light.
The gravy's got
a little bit of spice to it
from the pepper
and the hot sauce.
Mmm. Nice job, man.
Excellent.
The gravy is awesome.
The biscuits are to-die-for.
These are the best, by far.
The biscuits and gravy
is what I fell in love with.
My aunt had been coming here
for 30-something years,
and I'm keeping
the tradition going.
- One biscuit at a time.
- Exactly.
You hear that a lot
around here.
Generations of my family
have been coming here.
It's definitely a landmark
in Salt Lake City.
It's a throwback to the '30s.
Order up.
And to old-time cooking.
Mmm.
It doesn't matter what you get
here. It's great.
Expect to be wowed.
You got to dig it, man.
Great history to this place.
I love it.
She sent the e-mail?
It's a great place.
This is the place to be.
Yeah.
I knew your car would look great
in front of this place.
So now you're gaming
for a ride right now.
There you go.
I like the way she rolls.
Our next breakfast stop
is at the South Jersey Shore
on Long Beach Island.
Now the locals around here know
that when the rain starts
coming in from the Atlantic,
well, they start coming
into Mustache Bill's diner
for hot coffee
and some homemade breakfast.
Would you like
some more coffee?
Might as well.
Coffee?
Yeah.
Just like you to call me "Flo,"
if you don't mind.
Want some more coffee,
ma'am?
Classic diner.
Classic New Jersey diner.
There's always somebody in here
that you know, you can talk to.
It's like going to your
family dining room table.
For homestyle
breakfast favorites...
It's great diner food.
I'm a diner freak.
It's every basic,
but it's every basic done
the best it can be done.
By Mustache Bill himself,
Bill Smith...
Order up.
Who's been doing it all his way,
including
the paper towel headbands...
It's hot back here.
...for the last 35 years.
I worked here as a kid
when I was 14.
In this one?
In this diner.
After going off to college,
he came back
and bought the place in 1972.
Is it half job, half hobby?
Half job, half love.
And totally what a Jersey diner
is supposed to be.
Really great, basic
American breakfast food.
Chipped Beef.
Like chipped beef
made fresh every day.
It's a classic.
I've been eating it
since I was a kid.
It's not a jerky.
It's not quite as dry as the
beef you use to make jerky.
It's like wet jerky.
Right.
Put it right on top,
and I press it flat.
We're getting real close
to incorporating this flour.
So we're gonna make
a roux.
There we go.
And into the hot milk.
No spill. No spill.
Fantastic dismount.
The crowd goes wild.
Three pats of butter.
White pepper.
That's it?
So, rye toast.
And there it is.
That's money.
The rye bread
is completely important.
Right.
Nice job, man.
Now at a classic diner,
you're gonna get pancakes.
I'm a pancake maniac.
Blueberry, strawberry,
banana walnut...
Chocolate chip pancakes.
And a soda.
Yes.
That's the only way to go.
...you can even
get them done freehand.
Look at that.
What is that?
That's a little
something different.
If you were looking
from inside my head,
you'd see that looks like
a mind from my perspective.
There we go.
That is crazy.
Look at that.
Scary, very scary.
And Bill's pancake weirdness
doesn't stop with my face.
Check out the Cyclops.
It is a little bit
of a strange combination
to have the egg
in the middle of the pancake,
but somehow,
Bill makes it works.
Okay.
It's time
for the blueberries now.
Are we ready?
Yeah.
Oh, you didn't break
the yolk?
No, we don't serve them
with broken yolks.
Oh.
Look at that.
That's up there in some
of the best pancake I've had.
That's what I want
to hear.
It's a great place.
Everything's delicious.
Probably the best diner
that I've ever been to
in my life.
Coming up
in Long Beach, California...
Energizer waffle bunny.
...the seaside spot
making the crowds go wild.
This is bananas,
and bananas is good.
Then we're cruising up
to Los Angeles...
I am blown away.
...for a savory spin
on donuts.
That could be dangerous.
You should limit people
to how many of those
they can have.
I'm cruising in --
well, actually,
let me correct myself.
I'm boating into a place called
Schooner or Later.
Now a schooner can be
a sailing vessel,
or it can be a large,
ice-cold chalice
of fermented hops.
But in my world,
Schooner or Later
is an off-the-hook eatery
in Long Beach, California.
Thank you.
Beautiful scenery,
great food.
Getting crazy everywhere.
Order of onion rings?
It's a big experience...
I wondered where
I had parked my four boats.
It's wonderful --
sit outside, sit by the boats.
...with big food...
You have like six or seven
friends that are coming?
I'll down that
in two minutes.
No.
Yeah.
There you go.
...a big weekend hangout...
It's Sunday Funday.
We get to hang out
with all our friends.
...with a big line of fans
who insist
it's worth the wait.
We're gonna wait
for an hour.
Two hours.
Oh, it's so worth it.
Mmm.
Fabulous.
An avocado,
some hollandaise sauce.
Awesome.
- And an awesome tradition.
- Everything okay?
I was coming in here
and eating with my father.
Denny Lund
and his sister, Denise,
grew up coming here
then bought the place
from the original owner,
a guy named Schultzie,
whose signature item
is still on the menu.
And that is
the Schultzie's Mess.
We inherited it from him.
I ordered the Mess.
Everything you want
in breakfast,
thrown on a plate,
just ready to roll.
Head chef Tony Galope
has been making the Mess
for 20 years.
So how many, do you think, is
the most you served in one day?
50, 60 sometimes.
In one day?
In one day.
Start with potatoes.
This is the mix of bell pepper,
ham, and onion.
And then we put two eggs.
Mix those together.
Put a little bit
of crust on it.
Then I put cheddar cheese
on the top.
Cover it.
That steams it a little bit
and melts the cheese.
Yeah,
it melted the cheese.
Got it.
Beautiful.
Couple pieces of toast.
Couple of toast.
And then it's all done.
And that's it.
Mmm.
Oh, that is good stuff.
See, I like this part.
Oh, crunchy part.
The onions and the pepper
still have crunch.
They're cooked and they're hot,
and they're warm,
but they've still got
a little crunch in them.
That's as good
as they come.
I see why
they call it the Mess.
I could eat hers
and mine together.
It's a mess, but it's good.
And they're making
more than a mess here.
Eggs Benedict -- the best ever.
Their
crab omelette's fabulous.
The crab omelette.
The Italian omelette
with marinara sauce
and the sausage --
really good.
They love a show.
You see them put an omelette
on the plate over there.
It folds over,
and it's steamy.
And it's filled with all sorts
of different good things.
And it's all
worth traveling for.
You should know we drove
all the way from Kansas
to come to Schooner's.
All the way from Kansas.
And I come from Oregon,
and when I come down here,
I always come
to Schooner or Later.
I'm from
Grand Rapids, Michigan.
From Boynton Beach,
Florida.
Lake Worth, Florida.
And you're from...
I'm the local.
The Italian omelette.
The crab omelette.
And the Mess.
Between the visitors
and the regulars,
they can serve 1,000 people
on an average Sunday.
And a whole lot of them
are going for this.
I ordered a Belgian waffle
with bananas, strawberries,
and blueberries.
It's very good.
We just keep going
and going and going.
Sometimes we got five --
You're like
the energizer waffle bunny.
When the timer
screams "bring,"
and then it's done.
What does the timer do?
"Bring!"
How? I don't understand.
Does it go "bring"?
A watched waffle --
There you go.
Just one ding.
Oh, look at that.
It's got a banana and strawberry
and blueberries.
Whipped cream
on the top.
Mmm.
That's a great waffle.
How nice the fresh blueberry
and everything.
What did you think
of the waffle?
It was very good,
very good.
Very good, big?
Big waffle?
Yeah.
It's all big.
And more than that,
it's real, fresh-cooked,
what you want,
the way you want it.
Spinach and something.
Egg whites.
Even as busy
as Schooner or Later is,
they seem like
they do the egg whites,
do the egg white
omelettes.
Always.
Whatever you ask.
And they have
great spinach.
Every Sunday.
Don't miss it.
Come down to the shore,
have a little Mess.
It kind of cures everything.
I love this little place.
If I won the lottery tomorrow,
I wouldn't change
a thing about this.
Everything all right?
It's a piece of us,
and we truly enjoy it.
It's not just pretending.
It's all about
atmosphere here -- very fun.
But I think we've just kind of,
over time,
become an institution.
They just come here
for the day.
They don't make
any other plans.
They say,
"What are we doing today?
We're going to Schooner."
And that's it.
This is bananas,
and bananas is good.
Hey, banana.
I'm here in the historic core
of Los Angeles
by Fifth and Main,
an area they used to call
"The Nickel."
Now, I'm gonna visit a place
that's doing
some diner favorites
but with, you know,
California flair.
It's a kind of place
you can really find yourself.
Time to check out Nickel Diner.
Tofu Scramble.
This is one-of-a-kind.
Hangover Helper.
This is one-of-a-kind
no matter where you go.
You think?
Meringue on mannequins?
Upside down floor lamps.
No.
Donuts smothered in bacon?
A lovely surprise.
Donut with bacon?
Everybody's looking
for a surprise.
And everybody wants
a little journey.
Especially with Monica May's
doing the driving.
Catfish is up.
After 17 years in the food biz,
she decided
to open her own joint
with her pal
Kristen Trattner.
The dessert's
all made here.
We found this place.
It was
an abandoned restaurant.
It looks like it's
from circa 1940.
It is.
And now, they're making
diner food...
This is tofu.
...their way.
S'mac and cheese?
Mac and cheese
with a little bit of spice.
Pulled pork hash
with the main.
Their desserts are great.
All made here,
all made fresh.
And all made
by real-deal pastry chef,
Sharlena Fong.
You make your own
handmade Pop-tart.
You make
a Ding-Dong-like dessert.
And get a load of this one.
Bacon donuts!
Bacon always makes
everything better.
Isn't it weird when
you bite into donut texture
and then you get
crunchy bacon texture?
I guess
we'll have to see.
First, we start off
with some AP flour.
All-purpose flour.
Dry yeast.
Yes.
Add our eggs.
The Rocky Balboa Gatorade.
Some whole milk,
and give that a stir.
This is also
all-purpose flour.
This allows yeast
to activate.
Cracks will form
in the flour.
And this way,
I know it's ready to go.
That's from the yeast?
Yes.
Oh, okay, see,
this is why I don't bake.
Now, what happens?
We add flour, salt,
and sugar mixture.
And now...
Eggs.
Now we have our hook.
Captain.
Turn this on
for 15 minutes.
Okay, are we ready
to make donuts?
Well, now we have to add
room-temperature butter.
Six more minutes.
We're gonna let it rise
for two hours,
and then
we let it sit over night.
I know. It's long.
For a donut?
So this has rested
overnight.
We add a little more flour.
Give me that.
I'll show you.
A little bit more, yeah.
And now, we're get
to roll this thing out.
Smells good.
Now we're gonna
cut out donuts.
We can cut out
the hole after,
and then that's what
the small cutter's for.
Oh.
So we continue
to punch these out,
take the holes
out of them,
let them rise,
and then we're gonna fry them?
Right.
How hot's the oil?
380.
380. Dig it.
The bad boys are fried up.
Our glaze is
with the confectioner's sugar
and the maple syrup.
The bacon --
just regular, old bacon
that we cooked down
and chopped up.
Still a little warm.
All right, we may be able
to work with that.
So we're just gonna take
the donut, dip, dip,
and then glaze
the whole side of it.
And then
we dip it in the bacon.
And that's it.
Mmm.
Wow.
That's great.
That could be dangerous.
You should limit people to
how many of those they can have.
It's as good
as you would expect.
People are happy,
and that's the best part.
Brilliance.
It's comfort food.
Bacon burger.
I got to tell you.
I am blown away.
Thank you.
Up next,
in Santa Rosa, California...
Nothing wrong with that.
...an amazing program serving up
the bomb breakfast...
Let's go make
some huevos rancheros.
...while helping the community
at the same time.
Watch out for this guy, huh?
15 years old.
So here I am
in Santa Rosa, California --
my home town.
Now my first restaurant,
Johnny Garlic's,
is just about a half mile
that way.
Today is a very special
"Triple D" for me,
'cause I'm getting
to visit a place
where the chef was once
the chef educator
at a juvenile detention center.
She's now opened
her own local restaurant,
where she's giving
underserved youth
an opportunity
to get the experience
and education
in the restaurant biz.
It is my privilege
to introduce you
to WOW -- Worth Our Weight.
Pick up, huevos rancheros.
The kids' cooking is amazing.
Scrambled eggs
with cream cheese and lox.
This is my mom, Penny,
and my dad, Jim.
They're the ones that turned me
on to this joint.
Guy, this is about the best
brunch I've ever had.
And the price?
Polenta and chicken sausage.
Well, that's up to you.
People pay what they feel
that it's worth.
And everyone's a volunteer,
from founder
Evelyn Cheatham...
I do it because I love it.
...right down to some ambitious,
food-loving
culinary apprentices.
Evelyn's the chef.
You're the sous chef.
Right.
You cooked my breakfast
for me two years ago.
Oh, still talk
about that.
And Nick Wilkinson's
still wowing the brunch crowd.
Order up.
Huevos rancheros.
Huevos rancheros, it doesn't get
much better than that.
Huge, fresh pulled pork --
delicious.
Okay, pork butt,
how we doing it?
We're gonna give it a rub
with some salt and pepper.
Gonna leave it fat up?
Yup.
So as the fat cooks off,
it renders down across
the sides.
We're gonna roast it at 500,
about 45 minutes.
Okay, now what?
We're gonna add
some onions, carrots...
Some sweetness
from the carrots.
...and some
chipotle peppers.
Dried jalapeños.
Nice.
And now some water
almost to the top of the meat,
but you want
a little bit showing.
Cook this uncovered?
Yup.
200 --about eight hours.
Okay,
What are we onto know?
We're making
a pico de gallo.
First, we're gonna chop up
some onion.
Good knife skills,
my friend.
And now you go your tomato.
So, now, the jalapeños,
you gonna give those a mince?
Yup.
Want to get those nice and fine
so you don't have
these big nuggets of fire
sitting in there.
And we put a little cilantro
in there.
Oh, this just
gets better with time
when you let this
set up.
A little salt and pepper.
Okay.
Some lime juice.
Stir it up.
So do you
let this set up
for a few hours
before you serve it?
Yeah, usually overnight
or a couple hours.
Nothing wrong with that.
Let's go make some
huevos rancheros.
Let's do it.
So the pork is done.
The final step of that
was it got the tomatoes?
Yeah, chopped tomatoes.
Pico de gallo is made.
Where we at?
Three tortillas
on the grill.
The beans,
we soak overnight.
Add carrots, onion, a little bit
of the pico de gallo juice
and then let it simmer
about an hour.
We'll strain them off,
a little salt,
and then just let
that sit there warming.
Put a little cheddar
on these tortillas.
Some Monterey Jack
on it.
Big seller here,
the huevos rancheros?
Yeah, the huevos are.
"Huevos" being the eggs.
A little olive oil,
a little butter,
and now the egg.
Add some cheddar cheese,
a little bit of Jack.
Give it a flip.
Roll it.
Let that cheese melt up
and take that off.
Tortilla's over here.
Put the beans on.
Nice.
Is this one serving?
Yes, sir.
Now the egg,
pulled pork on the side.
Something nice like that.
Put a little bit
of our pico de gallo.
Pico de me-o.
And just a little bit
of cilantro leaf for garnish.
I got to try this first.
Mmm.
Nicely seasoned.
A little bit of heat
from that chipotle,
some of that pico de gallo.
Oh. Here's what I like --
You do the right steps.
You take the time, two days
to make simple breakfast.
You see that
on a lot of menus
but not handmade
like they do it here.
Wow. Mmm.
Great job, Nick.
Thank you.
Here's your
huevos rancheros.
You looking for something
that's really good? This is it.
It's perfect.
And the place itself,
it's just nourishing
in every way.
Side of potatoes.
You think this is
a good opportunity?
- It's a great opportunity.
- Huevos for the huevos.
This is the place to learn.
I feel like
I can do more in life.
Bread pudding!
I love it here.
It feels great to be here,
besides the fact
that it makes your mouth
and your stomach really happy.
Here is
your bagel and lox.
The food is phenomenal.
The baked goods here
are amazing.
Your lemon bar.
The scones are so good.
Scratch baked
by another young culinarian,
15-year-old Jessie Hayes.
He's a master.
All right, Jess.
It's you and me,
buddy.
Lead me into this.
These are
actually nectarines.
Nectarine scones?
Yes.
We're going to start off by
putting the flour in the bowl.
All-purpose flour -- AP?
Yes.
We're going to add
some baking powder.
It's a leavening agent.
Yeah,
and some salt for flavor,
sugar, add the butter.
We're just gonna mix this up
a little bit.
About that size
is a good size for butter.
We're going to add
the cream next.
Heavy cream.
Not sweetened, though?
No. And then finally,
we're gonna add the fruit.
It's just gonna be
a real light final mix.
Yeah,
just to get the cream
in there
with the dry ingredients.
Looking good.
That's it.
Now we're ready
to form our dough.
Sprinkle some flour
on the bench.
Just gonna try and not work
with it too much.
What happens if you do?
The butter will melt,
and it won't bake very well.
I'm going to cut it
in half.
And then you've got
your other three
that are ready to go?
Right.
Lay it out
on a sheet pan.
Put them in the freezer
for about an hour.
All right,
what do we do next?
Butter the top,
just kind of lightly sprinkle it
with sugar.
It's going to give it a nice
brown-golden texture to it.
And then just put them
in the oven.
What are we
gonna bake them at?
425 for about
20 to 25 minutes.
Which one do you like?
I kind of like that one.
All right,
then I'm gonna try this one.
Mmm.
Those, I love.
It's totally moist.
Nice crunch to the outside.
And the fresh fruit
inside of it.
Getting the nectarine in there,
so sweet and juicy.
It won't fit.
That was a fantastic scone.
And here's your scone.
It's really buttery and flaky.
You can really taste
the nectarine.
It's excellent.
Watch out
for this guy, huh?
15 years old.
And doing it all
on his own time.
Bread pudding.
They all are.
So I want to do something
for them.
Let's bring Evelyn
and the entire crew
from WOW out here
so they can see the donation
from the Guy Fieri Foundation --
the WOW cart.
Yeah!
So, Evelyn
and all the team here at WOW,
I mean,
the name should be "WOW,"
because I think everybody
walks out here going, "Wow."
Worth Our Weight,
an incredible experience for me,
I think for everybody
that comes here and eats,
for everybody
that's been watching.
We wanted to give something
to make you say, "Wow."
I got an opportunity
in the restaurant business
starting out selling pretzels
when I was a kid.
Had a great community around me
that helped me build this cart
and gave me the opportunity
to get into the business.
Now, it's your turn.
So this is a donation
from me and from my foundation
for the WOW team
to share all the great things
that you do at WOW
and to make it portable,
to let Northern California
try those fantastic scones
and all the baked goods
that you do.
It cooks.
It cools.
There's three bay sinks.
There's a handwash sink.
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is a little mini WOW restaurant.
Oh, my god.
This is so great.
That is so great.
This is gonna be
a wonderful opportunity
to not only sell food
and make money for WOW,
but it's gonna be
a great opportunity for you
to interact with your community
and for them to see
just how incredible
you all really are.
WOW is happening
because of all of you.
When you come
to Sonoma County,
when you're in Santa Rosa,
you got to come see WOW.
So that's it
for this Flavortown roadtrip.
But don't you worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
Oh, I just got to keep up
with this guy.
When I watch your show,
you're ahead of everybody.
I'm usually the one rowing
and steering the boat.
Right now, I'm just holding
onto the back rope.
Don't fall in the water.