Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Is the anticipation
killing you, or what?
...whether on a plate
or a bowl...
Cut.
...Cajun or soul...
Mmm. Mmm!
...we got a full hour of good
old-fashioned Southern cookin'.
That was unbelievable.
We're talkin'
North Carolina dumplings...
They're ready to go.
Go time.
...South Carolina collards...
And these right here
are some money greens.
...a killer
Kentucky fried po' boy...
I'd eat that every day.
And some St. Louis
Southern comfort.
Just like mom
couldn't make.
Just like mama
couldn't make!
Then we're headin' north...
It's cold out here.
...for biscuits and gravy
in Oregon...
I could be eatin' a paper towel
with that gravy on it. Wow.
...N'awlins in Indiana...
Once you cross over
the threshold here,
you're in Louisiana.
...and good old gizzards --
yeah, gizzards -- in Michigan.
This place is a trip.
So, get ready for a down-home,
down-South food-coma
kind of show.
This is amazing.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
-- Captions by VITAC --
Closed Captions provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC.
You know, on "Triple D,"
we've hit joints
that are all about pizza,
all about burgers.
We've even hit a joint
that's all about fried carp.
And today, ladies and gentlemen,
we take another culinary leap
to visit a joint that's all
about the tender, flaky --
Is the anticipation
killing you, or what?
The tender, flaky, gravy-topped
Southern delicacy
known as biscuits.
Welcome to Portland's
Pine State Biscuits...
Full tray comin' up.
The best biscuit ever.
About three minutes
on biscuits.
This is the perfect bite.
Biscuit
and huckleberry jam.
And a biscuit
with sausage gravy.
Do you run here?
Some good home-cooked
comfort food.
I got some gravy comin'.
...all served up
by college buddies Brian Snyder,
Walt Alexander,
and Kevin Atchley...
Hot tray.
We're all
from North Carolina.
All of you?
Yep.
How y'all doin'?
...who ended up in Portland,
reconnected,
and opened this place.
Why biscuits?
'Cause we missed 'em.
People needed a place
they could stop by
and get a good,
hearty breakfast.
Like this
North Carolina classic.
The best biscuits and gravy.
So get me started.
Flour.
All-purpose?
Unbleached. Baking powder.
Baking soda.
Why the two?
That's what gives us
the best rise, flakiness.
Little bit of salt.
And we whisk this together.
Put the dry ingredients
together first.
Then we got the wet mix.
Buttermilk.
Is that buttermilk light?
Reduced fat.
We got some full-fat yogurt.
Some eggs.
We'll whisk
all this together,
and then we shred
the butter.
Whoa. We're gonna what?
Oh, this is awesome.
Dude, I have seen biscuits
all over the world,
and I have never seen
butter shredding.
It's rock-hard frozen.
Exactly.
It's gonna create flaked
deliciousness.
You got it.
Check that out.
That's nuts.
Yeah.
Actually, it's butter.
So now we got to act fast
because we don't want
that butter to melt,
right?
That's right.
So we get it
incorporated.
So it doesn't separate?
That's right.
All you do
is add that liquid
and give it, like, two or three
spins and that's it?
That's all she wrote.
Flour the board.
We're bringin' out
the dough.
You just
incorporated it
enough to get it
out of the bowl,
but you still got
some work to do, correct?
Exactly.
They are hand-built.
We're ready to roll.
So we'll roll this out,
and we'll do some foldin'.
Not only do you have the flour
creating all of this layer,
you're creating layer as you
fold along top of each other.
Exactly.
So we're ready to cut.
Exact right size.
Goes in the oven.
Just below 400.
12 to 15 minutes.
Hit it
with a little butter.
About 2, 3 minutes
before we pull 'em out.
I'm gonna try to pick out
the one I think is the best.
That one.
Oh.
Well, now you've done
broke it.
Well, let's cover it
with gravy.
Olive oil. Pureed onions.
Ground pork. Water.
Give that a stir.
And some flour.
Sausage spice mix.
Cayenne, salt, pepper, nutmeg,
coriander, thyme, and sage.
Heavy cream, whole milk.
Make a butter
and flour roux.
Add the roux.
Maple syrup.
Look at that.
Little chives.
Little paprika
for some color.
I dig it. Okay.
Mmm. That is some of the best
texture in a biscuit
I've ever had.
It has the flakiness,
and it's light,
but there's real
substance to it.
But, then again,
I could be eatin' a paper towel
with that gravy on it.
Wow.
Mmm! Killer.
I'd say these are some of
the best biscuits I've ever had.
Flaky and delicious.
Biscuits comin'.
It's a biscuit that can handle
whatever you want to put
in this biscuit.
Yeah, "whatever" --
like stewed apples.
You got to have a side
of huckleberry jam,
kind of an Oregon deal.
Shiitake mushroom gravy.
My favorite's
The Double Down Moneyball --
Two biscuits,
gravy all over the place,
and then an egg on top.
Biscuits goin' in.
It's a biscuit place,
but the fried chicken
is the best in town.
So you know where this is goin'.
This giant sandwich.
The Reggie.
Right.
You see, Ryan wanted to
name his son Reggie,
and his wife said no way.
So he figured, hey, the next
best thing was a sandwich.
First things first, we're gonna
make some fried chicken.
We'll make up
the marinade or the soak.
Little more
of that buttermilk.
Little cayenne.
And then
we'll whisk that up.
Then we'll slice up
the chicken.
Whoa.
Thin fried chicken.
It's biscuit portion.
Soak this for 24 hours.
Okay.
Make up the dredge.
So, more
of that biscuit flour?
This is actually
self-rising.
Coarse ground pepper.
So we'll whisk this up.
Then we got the egg wash.
A little hot sauce.
Yep.
Wow.
Dare you to lick it.
No, thanks.
So, then we'll season
the chicken.
More seasoning.
Garlic salt, salt, pepper,
and Cajun seasoning.
Whoa.
We'll dip it.
And then the flour
on top of that.
You have a tendency
with some of those spices,
they can burn, so the closer
they are down to the bird,
better off you are.
You got it.
Dude knows
what's goin' on.
And we'll fry it up.
Look at these. That is some
good-lookin' fried chicken.
You just showed your North
Carolina passport just now.
We get a biscuit.
Fried chicken, bacon,
gravy, and cheddar.
How do you get around
on that one?
Don't be shy.
I ain't that kind of guy.
You know the hunch?
Yeah.
I know the hunch.
Mmm.
Oh, you do.
That's ridiculous.
Everybody comes together.
That's right.
I love it.
It's got everything on it.
I had my Reggie and then
most of my wife's Reggie.
This place is great.
It's not just bacon
and eggs and hash browns.
It's something
really unique.
Two more goin' down.
Simple and delicious.
Best biscuits in Portland
I've found.
I'll come back, for sure.
Guys, congratulations.
Oh, appreciate it.
Dynamite place.
Killer biscuits.
Up next,
it's St. Louis, Missouri.
Oho-ho!
Big-time,
home-cooked favorites...
What is this,
about 30 pounds?
...that are doin' the body good.
When your heart's in it,
and when you believe in it,
and it's --
it's more than just food...
That's soul food.
Then it's soul food.
When you think of Southern food,
you know --
fried chicken, mac and cheese,
collard greens --
the question comes to mind,
when does Southern food
turn in to soul food?
Here at a place called
Sweetie Pie's in St. Louis,
people tell me
it's all in the heart
of the folks who are makin' it.
There's a lot of love
goin' into it.
Hey, sweetie,
how you doin'?
You got to put some love
in there, seriously.
Is everything
all right?
This chicken
is made with love.
Is everything
all right over here?
And the woman dishin' out
the love is Robbie Montgomery.
She's been servin' soul food
to St. Louis since '97.
The chicken and the fish,
the ribs, the pork chops,
the macaroni and cheese,
I mean, it's everything.
What's your favorite thing
to get here?
This, right here.
Definitely, the macaroni
and cheese is my favorite.
It's probably the best mac
and cheese I've ever had.
You want greens, too?
Dressing and greens.
Good texture, crisp.
Sweet potatoes.
Can I have
the baked chicken?
Chicken. Chicken.
It's so tender.
See how it's fallin'
off the bone?
The, uh, fried chicken
reminds me of my grandmother's,
and the cornbread, the way
she used to make it.
It's so good,
you don't need any butter.
Nobody cooks
like Sweetie Pie -- nobody.
Nobody?
Nobody.
So I got to go see
about my pork steaks.
And get this...
It's ready.
...Robbie didn't start out
as a chef.
Okay, Bobby, I need
my turkey wings back in.
She started out as a singer.
Met Ike and Tina Turner.
How crazy is that?
And from there, went from that.
That was crazy.
And you used to cook
on the road.
Yeah, because things
were segregated,
and we weren't allowed in a lot
of the better restaurants.
But we had
electric skillets,
and we would cook
in our room.
So, we got one, two, three.
You got your next pan
of chicken ready?
And after almost 40 years,
she left one stage
and jumped up on another.
Peach cobbler up.
I put down the mike
and picked up a pot.
All of these recipes...
Are my mom's.
Are your mom's...
My mom's.
With your Robbie spin
on it
'cause I got to believe that
there's always a Robbie spin.
It is. It is.
Durin' my travels,
I picked up little things.
Little...
Add 'em. Yeah.
Little tit-tats and stuff
and add it to my recipe.
Like her macaroni and cheese.
I've been makin' this
about 40 years.
Right out
of eighth grade.
Out of eighth grade,
exactly.
Well, we're gonna start
with the pasta.
Now, we're gonna add two pounds
of Velveeta cheese.
Nothin' but Velveeta.
Noth --
No imitation.
Don't give me any...
Don't stop
no place else.
Don't give me imitation
imitation cheese.
That's right. No.
So then we got
a pound of...
Cheddar.
...cheddar.
Colby and jack,
we got a pound of that.
Then next, we gonna add
two heapin' tablespoons
of sour cream.
Just, sunshine, so you know,
that's not a tablespoon.
Well, I -- You're right.
That's your spoon.
That's my tablespoon.
Then we've got butter
and margarine,
salt, pepper, and sugar...
Five eggs. You can crack,
and I'll whisk.
...a mess of milk.
How much of that?
No idea. Just some.
Just some?
We're gonna top it
with the fancy mild.
What is this,
about 30 pounds?
Feels like it.
I tell you, it's a heavy pan.
That's ready.
Look at the crispy crunch
on top of that!
Mmm.
Good macaroni, okay.
It's real.
The pasta is real.
The mixture
of the cheeses inside.
That does me proud to see you
eatin' it more than once.
Give me a stool and a bib,
I'll be here for a day.
Just like mom
couldn't make.
Just like mama
couldn't make!
It makes you
feel like...
Everyone talks
about Sweetie Pie's.
It's great.
Hi.
And for Robbie,
what matters most
is makin' sure everyone's
lovin' what she's servin'.
I wanted to still deal
with the public.
Okay.
I'm-a go out here.
I go out in the dining room,
make sure everybody's happy.
You look good, too.
You didn't know
that was me up there.
Here you go, baby.
Thank you.
You know what?
I like the service.
Okay.
Is everything all right
for you ladies over here?
And now her son, Tim, is
following Mom into the business.
We're gonna change
spots.
This is my mom's dream.
I can't let my mom's dream die
no matter what.
And that means cookin'
for everyone else
the way Robbie cooked for him.
All I know is,
I been eatin' my mom's cooking
before I was born, you know,
since before I was born.
Yeah, you were.
Yeah.
And I like it.
All of his favorite recipes
done the same as always,
like Robbie's famous
smothered pork.
We gonna flour it
and fry it.
Fry it?
Fry it.
And then
we gonna smother it.
I think the fryin' it
will have smothered it.
You just stack 'em up
in there,
and then they go to
the fryer?
Into the deep fryer,
exactly.
It's like fryin' a pork chop
in your hot tub.
Exactly.
But that looks ready?
That looks ready.
What am I puttin' on,
onions and what?
Onions and my little
special seasoning.
And your little special,
"I'm not gonna tell ya."
That's right.
This is gravy
made with that dark roux.
Uh, dark roux, right.
That's it.
And this process just
keeps goin' on all day long.
All day long.
Cookin' and makin' it,
cookin' and puttin' it
and takin' and now goin'
and servin' it.
Look at the size.
Mmm.
Oho. Oho.
Ho-ho!
The texture of the meat
and the flavor
and the deep richness
of that roux.
Thank you.
That gravy --
that is so good.
Oh, great.
And they just keep packin' in
for the smothered pork
and everything else
Robbie is making.
Taste like food you ate
when you're at home?
Just like it.
Just like it?
Mm-hmm.
And you can kind of feel
the family atmosphere here.
Wings, wings, uh-huh.
This is the real deal
all the time.
You know what? I got one
disappointment, though.
I wish I had an extra stomach
to eat some more food.
That's my only disappointment.
It's really soul food.
When your heart's in it,
and when you believe in it,
and it's more
than just food...
That's soul food.
Then it's soul food.
That's right,
from the soul.
Coming up,
in Charlotte, North Carolina...
Show-off.
...serious Southern staples...
Tell me
about chicken and dumplings.
...by land and by sea.
There's a lot of crunch
on that cake.
I'm here
in Charlotte, North Carolina.
Now, any time I roll into town,
I got to come by
and see my buddy Greg
at the Penguin Drive-in.
You remember --
deep friend pickles,
pimiento cheese,
the Full-blown Hemi.
Before I go in there,
I got to go about 100 yards
down the way here
and check out another joint
for "Triple D."
These folks are serving up
some Southern classics.
This is Dish.
Meatloaf up.
It's comfort food.
It's like going to Grandma's.
Chicken and dumplings.
They're fantastic.
Black-eyed peas.
All the plates come
with a deviled egg
and the biscuit, as well.
It's just great, home-cooked,
Southern-style food.
In a joint run by a couple
of former nightclub owners...
Hey, sweeties.
Originally,
it was my idea.
...Penny Craver
and Maggie Stubbs...
Let's head on back.
...who decided it was time
to serve up more than beer.
We all grew up eating good,
Southern home cooking.
Mac and cheese,
table eight.
The kind that brought head cook
Kirstie Floyd to the South...
Order up.
...after cooking in Europe
and all over the U.S.
Meatloaf sandwich.
Most popular item
on the menu?
Chicken and dumplings.
- That's all I ever get.
- Seriously?
I don't think I've ever
gotten anything else.
Southern classic,
and they do it very well here.
It reminds me
of when I was a kid.
The dish I would always
look forward to
that my dad would make
would be chicken and dumplings.
Tell me about
chicken and dumplings.
Okay.
Start off with a raw bird.
Baste it with a little bit
of butter,
some salt and pepper mix,
and put it
right into the oven.
And 350 degrees?
350 degrees.
55 minutes.
Roast it
to give the roasting flavor
to get some of that flavor
out of the bones, into the meat.
So the bird's
cooled down now.
for the stock,
to get some of that flavor
out of the bones, into the meat.
and now, it's time
to "shredify"?
Shredify.
Do you ever growl
when you do it?
Depends on the day.
Yeah.
After we separate all the
chicken, we'll put that aside.
Then, we're gonna
start making the stock.
Add the bone and the skin, which
we pulled from the chicken.
About two pitchers
of water.
And the broth.
Some of the fat?
Oh, yeah.
The good stuff.
Some diced white onion.
Pepper --
a lot of pepper.
Generous.
Some celery salt because
that's always really good
to pull
the chicken flavor out.
Granulated garlic,
and granulated onion, as well.
How long
is it gonna boil for?
It'll boil
about 10, 15 minutes.
Cool it just a tiny bit
so it's manageable. Strain it.
Strain it out,
back into the pot.
Now we're gonna get
into making the dumplings.
The dumplings.
All righty.
Start with flour.
Four eggs and a half pound
of melted butter.
Mix it up.
Okay.
We're gonna form it.
All right. Flour.
And just roll it out
about a quarter-inch.
You don't want them
too thin
because they tend
to disintegrate
when you get them
into the hot water.
And we don't want that.
You want them to puff up.
Puff up.
Right.
Just cut them
in little squares.
Oh, look at her doing it
the backwards way.
Show-off.
Here we go.
Made it look so easy.
Thanks.
Handmade at the Dish.
We'll have all these
ready to go.
They're ready to go.
Go time!
Add our already pulled
chicken.
We got white and dark
in there?
Oh, yeah.
I'm gonna add
our dumplings.
You don't want to dump
all at one time
because they tighten up as soon
as they hit that hot water,
and then you got
yourself this ball.
Big mass of dumpling.
We're keeping them separated.
We're gonna add a basic roux,
just butter and flour.
But you're also gonna
get some thickener
just coming out
of that dumpling dough.
And let it go
for about 30 minutes
to cook those dumplings?
Absolutely.
Ready for a taste?
Oh, look at
all the chicken.
Mouth is already
starting to water.
Look at that,
nice and thick.
Look at that dumpling
right there.
Mmm.
Awesome.
Really awesome.
Easier if I get it
up to the...
There you go.
We got a super-tender
dumpling...
And I like the fact that
you roasted the chicken,
so it's got
real chicken flavor.
We've got homemade chicken stock
with roux,
very simply seasoned.
That is down-home
chicken and dumplings.
Wonderful.
Mmm.
Cut.
I said to...
The dumplings are my favorite
part. Just super yummy.
The chicken is really fresh.
Lots of flavor,
which is a trademark
of everything
they put out here.
Chicken
and black bean burrito.
This is the kind of place
I like to work.
I get a lot more
creativity.
You got the Cajun meatloaf.
The Burrito Del Sur.
Sweet potatoes are
going in a burrito.
Southern goes Mexico.
There you go.
A wonderful blend of flavors.
Pot roast.
I can see Mom
in the kitchen cooking.
That's how good it is?
Yeah.
Handmade from scratch,
like this Southern classic...
Patties up.
...salmon patties.
Absolutely phenomenal.
But these don't start
in a can.
Each time you guys get a fish
in, you break it down?
Yeah, I do.
I like that attitude.
Slice about 8-ounce pieces,
dice it in little cubes,
soak those in water.
Put all of our ingredients
together.
Parsley, pulverized onions
because you want that juice.
You want it to break down
because you're not
precooking the onions,
so you don't want big chunk
of onion in there.
Exactly.
Five whisked eggs.
And have a binder --
mustard.
That's a lot
of whole grain.
You'd be surprised, though.
It's not that sharp.
Mayo. Celery.
Squeezed lemon juice,
lemon zest, dill weed.
That's a lot of dill.
But dill and salmon
go hand in hand.
They do.
Worcestershire sauce.
Okay.
So mix it all up,
with the dill, the whole grain.
See, it seemed like a lot,
but when you mix it up,
it's evenly dispersed.
It is.
This is just regular
white-bread bread crumb
with a little bit
of butter on it.
And we like to let this sit
for a little while.
Let some of those bread crumbs
absorb some of the moisture,
kind of tighten
this whole thing up.
Then we'll form the patty.
Roll it
in some Japanese bread crumbs.
Oh, so panko.
Over to the flat top.
Oh, and they go
pretty thick.
Oh, yeah.
And now I push them down.
A little squish.
Four minutes each side?
Four minutes each side,
exactly right.
We're gonna make
honey orange butter,
which comes
with the salmon patties.
Presoftened butter.
And then goes the...
Honey.
Then we'll add
a half an orange.
There you go.
Okay.
All right.
Looks like they're done.
That's a lot
of salmon patty.
It is.
The butter for you.
Okay.
Mmm. That's nice.
That's a lot
of salmon patty.
It is.
Dill right off the bat.
Salmon comes in.
Here's what I dig
about it --
There's a lot of crunch
on that cake.
Without having to
deep-fry it, as well.
Without deep-frying it.
The nice little touch
of adding the butter
brings it all together.
Wonderful.
Good job.
Thank you.
Salmon patties.
It's fresh, it's simple,
spiced just right.
The honey orange butter --
that's what makes it pop.
They're excellent, good as
everything else on the menu.
Barbecue slider.
Fantastic, wholesome, good food.
That was on point.
You come in,
and it's just like home.
You don't feel like
you have to dress up.
You do have to wear
clothes and stuff.
You can't come, like,
in your pajamas.
That's like seeing you guys
here in a couple Snuggies.
Up next on this hour-long
Southern hoedown...
Want to see
the dance I do?
No, we don't
want to see that.
...in Lexington,
South Carolina...
...a country spot
doing major multitasking.
Farmers' market, garden shed,
of course, restaurant.
...to get the flavor jets going.
Right now, there's
a mini Niagara Falls
going on in my mouth.
This is Route 1, right between
Columbia, South Carolina,
and Augusta, Georgia,
in a little town on the Carolina
side called Lexington.
Now, what we have here
was a farmers' market,
and then it turned
into a garden center.
And when you have a garden
center, what do you add next?
Yep, of course, a restaurant.
This is The Farmer's Shed.
Fried chicken
and your succotash.
It's typical Southern food.
And then veggies.
Macaroni and cheese,
collard greens.
This is home cooking.
This is what I grew up with.
- Just like Shirley Sease.
- Good evenin'.
You grew up as a farming
family's daughter.
Yep. And then
I married a farmer.
Moved from one farm
to another farm.
To running this farmer's market,
where, eight years ago,
she started cooking
Southern classics
straight from her own farm.
These collard greens are great.
You grow these
here on your farm.
Yes.
I don't know that
everybody in this country
really appreciates
greens.
They should.
We got these
all chopped up ready to go.
And this is
what they look like.
Want to see
the dance I do?
No, we don't
want to see that.
First thing
we're gonna add is water.
I'll put a ham hock in.
Look at that.
Smoked ham hock.
Do you think I can
shoot it from back?
Do you clean up
your messes?
Hey!
Yeah!
I'm gonna add a little
chicken base to it,
just to give it
a little mph,
then some black pepper,
and then some salt.
And we got to cook this
for about 45 minutes
until the ham hock...
Comes apart.
Then we'll add
the collard greens.
Feel like I'm feeding horses
back in Ferndale.
Pop a lid on it.
How long do they cook?
20 to 25.
The collards
should be ready.
Wow, look how much
that cooks down.
Good for you.
Yeah.
That's my motto, always
eating what's good for me.
Okay.
Around here, we eat hot-pepper
vinegar over our collard greens.
Oh, yeah, around here,
we do, too.
Like that?
Mm-hmm.
Love me some collards.
Mmm. Those are tender,
sweet,
and a little bit of that
hock meat in there.
Little bit
of that hot-pepper vinegar.
I could chug that.
I've had greens
all over the country,
and these right here
are some money greens.
Those are worth
coming to try.
If you don't think you like
greens, come eat these.
Then, if you don't
like these,
well, then, you were
just never blessed
enough to like greens.
And I need
a side of collards.
She seasons them well.
It's really good.
With the ham hock, it just
melts the flavors together.
They introduced me
to collards here,
and now I have to
have them.
Got your pork chop
on this one.
I like how they have
the same menu on certain days.
So everybody kind of has their
day that they like to come for.
I just wait for Wednesdays
because on Wednesdays,
it's chicken day.
It's wonderful.
I want that piece.
Want that piece?
Look at that. Mmm.
What's the most
popular day?
Friday. Shrimp and grits
with tasso gravy.
I've tried it in other places,
and she has the best.
Okay, so how do we
start her off?
Let's make
the tasso gravy.
First thing we're gonna put in
is butter, then the leeks.
So we'll let these just
sweat down a little bit.
You're going to add
oregano, black pepper,
some Florida Bay seasoning,
paprika, chili powder,
some garlic powder.
Seasoned salt.
You're good.
Basil.
And a little bit
of thyme.
of French thyme.
Oh.
You know, I'm so...
And a little tomato juice,
a little sizzle there.
Clam juice.
Okay.
Next, half and half.
Now you're going to get
the roux in it?
And then we just have it
come back to a boil.
Right now, there's
a mini Niagara Falls
going on in my mouth.
You should smell this.
And this is tasso ham.
Oh, you said "try some ham."
Mmm, delicious.
And we're gonna cut
the heat off, and it's ready.
Now we're gonna make grits?
I love grits.
Good. I do too.
Local,
stone-ground grits.
Local.
So let's get into it.
I put the water in.
Next, we'll add the milk,
a stick of butter,
just a little salt.
We'll let it
come to a boil.
Then we'll add the grits.
Just good old grit making.
I'm the grit danada.
Got to try my grits,
you're gonna love them.
I promise
you'll be back.
Is that the consistency
you want?
Yes.
Now what?
We're gonna make
the shrimp.
I'm gonna put some butter.
I love somebody
who cooks with a hot pan.
Get her going.
Yeah, that's really hot.
How many shrimp?
All of them.
So just cook those up
till they get a little bit
of a...
A little pink.
And then we're gonna put
some tasso gravy on them.
We're not using
all this tasso.
We're not because we're putting
it in the back of a '67 Camaro
that's going back
to California.
Okay, want me to put
some grits on here?
Sure.
So the tasso sauce
is ready.
Now, can I have
some of the, uh...
Those are called
field peas.
And, uh, green beans?
Okay, let's try this.
Mmm.
This has everything.
Some seafood, little veggie
in there, little bit spicy.
Mmm, grits are
perfectly cooked.
Real texture to them,
but real creaminess to them.
The tasso and shrimp, this is
the dictionary definition of it.
You can find that dictionary
at the Flavortown library.
Great, delicious,
fantastic.
All right,
I got a shrimp and grits.
Grits are wonderful.
Smooth and creamy,
and they're the yellow grits,
which I love.
I love the tasso gravy.
It really brings out the flavor
in the shrimp.
I look forward to Fridays
to come to Miss Shirley's
and get
some shrimp and grits.
I love The Farmer's Shed.
I got Jefferson chicken.
These things are hot.
It beats any other Southern
cooking around here.
This is like Sunday dinner
at Granny's house.
And around here,
that means cornbread...
I love it.
...a Farmer's Shed
family recipe.
Well, we're gonna use
some yellow cornmeal
that is locally grown.
Uh-huh.
Self-rising cornmeal,
so some leavening agent
is already in it.
Yes. And salt.
That's a good start
we did right there --
didn't come out
of a box.
Add some flour
and some sugar.
See, it's gonna be good.
My secret ingredient.
It's a savory spice.
All right, then, we're gonna
put eight eggs in there.
Now, how much milk
we putting in?
Most of this.
We'll stir it and see.
You're gambling,
aren't you?
Mm-hmm.
Stir this up.
Is that the creaminess
that we're looking for?
We're right at it.
And we're gonna put this
in a hot skillet.
That skillet's
done some time.
We're gonna put some...
Butter-flavored oil.
We're gonna fill it up.
Look, that's already
starting to form up crust.
That pan is so hot
right now, you can't --
My hands from here,
still too hot to be next to.
Then we're going to top it
with some brown sugar.
Now, how long
and what temperature?
425 for about 25 minutes.
Cornbread is ready?
Ready.
What do you think?
Look at that.
What are those
over there?
What?
Oh, I guess nothing.
Look at the steam
coming off that thing.
All right, let me
get a piece of this.
Like that crunchy stuff.
Mmm, that tastes great
just by itself.
It's moist,
little bit of salt to it.
Sweet.
A little bit sweet.
I get some of that
butter note from it
from that buttery oil.
Mmm.
That is so sweet
on the top
that that little
sugar nugget I got,
that's almost like
a doughnut or a scone.
Great cornbread. You can stay
in South Carolina now.
I won't get run out.
Nope, you'll be fine.
Good old Southern cooking
right there.
Thank you.
All right,
and here's your cornbread.
It's almost creamy for a bread.
They take the extra time to cook
it the way it needs to be.
I feel like I'm part
of Shirley's family
when I'm sitting here
eating her food.
Did you enjoy
that chicken?
Yes, ma'am.
Good.
They just kind of take care
of everybody.
What is it that you like
most about this?
Dealing with the people
and serving people food.
How are the shrimp and grits
today?
And I'll tell you something.
I had some great food today.
That's a neat experience.
Farmers' market, garden shed,
of course, restaurant.
Good job.
Thank you.
Coming up,
in Frankfort, Kentucky...
I want you
to take a look at this.
...a funky joint
cooking up crazy crawfish...
A notch below insane.
...and piling on
the outrageous oysters.
This place
is off the chain.