HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
TOTALLY RETRO...
IT'S LIKE GOING
BACK HOME AGAIN.
THE PORTLAND JOINT THAT'S
A BACK-IN-TIME ROAD TRIP,
WHERE YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT THEY'RE DOING
TO THE HOMEMADE HASH...
BIG HANDFULS
OF BROWN SUGAR.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
SOMETHING I'VE NEVER SEEN.
THE INDIANA DINER
AND SODA SHOP...
(woman) YOU JUST HAVE TO KIND
OF SMUSH IT DOWN ON THE SIDE.
WHERE THEY'RE
DOING RETRO FLOATS
AND EVEN THE CHILI
COMES BY THE GLASS...
THAT'S A HOME RUN,
BUDDY.
AND THE CALIFORNIA
BURGER JOINT,
WHERE THE CLASSICS
GET A WHOLE NEW SPIN.
JUST WHAT YOU EXPECT
TO FIND AT ANY DRIVE-IN--
AN AHI BURGER--
YEAH, OF COURSE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
PORTLAND, OREGON, IS HOME
TO SO MANY GREAT THINGS--
THE NBA TRAIL BLAZERS,
MY GODDAUGHTER SOPHIA
AND A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
IN THE CENTER OF TOWN.
THE BYWAYS CAFé IS DECORATED
FROM HEAD TO TOE
WITH KNICKKNACK PADDYWHACKS
FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I FEEL LIKE I'M
AT A SWAP MEET.
YEAH.
I LIKE THE SUITCASES,
TOO, UP THERE.
THE SHRINE TREE
IN MYERS FLAT, CALIFORNIA--
THAT'S WHERE
I'M FROM.
REALLY?
I AM BACKWARDS
IN THE GRAND CANYON.
BUT IT'S NOT JUST
THE COLLECTION.
THAT MIGHT BE UP IN THE TOP
TACKIEST RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S A GOOD ONE,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S THE COMFORT FOOD--
HANDMADE AND OFF THE HOOK--
THAT DRAWS THE CROWD.
WE GO AS HOMEMADE
AS WE POSSIBLY CAN.
OWNERS COLLIN McFADYEN
AND MEGAN BRINKLEY
ARE RUNNING JUST THE KIND OF
PLACE THEY ALWAYS DREAMED OF.
WE'VE BOTH BEEN HERE SO LONG.
LIKE, I GREW UP HERE.
I STARTED WORKING HERE
RIGHT BEFORE I TURNED 24,
YOU KNOW?
(Guy) WHAT A NEAT
FEELING.
IT'S A SECOND HOME,
FOR SURE.
AND I THINK IT'S A SECOND HOME
FOR A LOT OF CUSTOMERS, TOO.
SORT OF A ROUTE 66
FEEL.
YEP.
A PLACE TO ENJOY MEMORIES
OF FAMILY VACATIONS
AND HEAPING PLATES
OF OLD-TIME FAVORITES.
IT'S THE BEST BREAKFAST
IN ALL OF DOWNTOWN PORTLAND.
(Guy) REALLY?
IT'S KILLER.
I'VE BEEN DYING TO SEE SOMEBODY
EAT THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
HOW IS THAT?
IT'S EXCELLENT. I GET IT
HERE EVERY TIME I COME.
I'M A CORNED BEEF
HASH JUNKIE.
AHA.
I HAVE TO GO TO MEETINGS
ABOUT MY CORNED BEEF HASH.
THE THING THAT I THINK MAKES
OUR CORNED BEEF HASH SO GOOD
IS THAT IT'S HOMEMADE
FROM START TO FINISH.
COLLIN BOILS THE CORNED BEEF
WITH GARLIC, BROWN SUGAR
AND PICKLING SPICE.
ON TOP OF WHAT IT'S
ALREADY BRINED WITH?
YES.
IT COMES BRINED, BUT YOU
WANT TO MAKE IT YOUR OWN.
THEN YOU THROW YOUR
LITTLE THING TO IT?
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA TAKE--
STONE-GROUND MUSTARD.
AND YOU HAVE TO DO THIS
WHEN IT'S HOT.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE'RE
GONNA USE FOR THE--
...THE HASH.
BIG HANDFULS
OF BROWN SUGAR.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
SOMETHING I'VE NEVER SEEN.
SO I'M MASSAGING IT
IN THERE.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
SOMETHING I'VE NEVER SEEN.
IT GOES INTO THE OVEN
FOR TEN MINUTES.
(whistling) WOW,
THAT SMELLS GOOD.
JUST FOR THE ACT
OF SCIENCE.
OKAY, THE ACT
THAT'S PHENOMENAL.
EXCELLENT.
SO THAT SITS THERE AND WORKS
TOGETHER A LITTLE BIT,
AND YOU HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL?
A LITTLE WATER,
ACTUALLY.
A LITTLE WATER
TO STEAM IT?
THIS IS THE LEAST-GREASY
CORNED BEEF HASH
YOU'VE EVER HAD
IN YOUR ENTIRE LIFE.
AND NO THIN-CUT
HASH BROWNS HERE.
COLLIN HITS IT WITH A BIG
HELPING OF HOMEMADE HOME FRIES.
I LIKE
THAT SEASONING...
YEAH, I LIKE
THAT ONE, TOO.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA, SALT
AND PEPPER, CAYENNE,
GARLIC POWDER.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THE SECRET IS? CUMIN.
CUMIN.
I LOVE CUMIN.
NOBODY ELSE PUTS
THAT IN THERE.
AND THEN
IT GETS BETTER.
YOU MELT THE CHEESE
RIGHT INTO IT?
YOU MELT YOUR CHEESE
RIGHT OVER THE TOP.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT LOOKS KILLER.
I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER HAD HASH
THAT'S HAD MELTED
CHEESE INTO IT.
THAT'S SOME
RIGHTEOUS HASH.
THANK YOU.
THAT IS GOOD.
ORDER UP, NATE.
COLLIN AND MEGAN ARE PUTTING
THEIR OWN UNIQUE SPIN
ON THE REST OF THE MENU, TOO.
(Guy) THAT'S A MONSTER
SET OF PANCAKES.
I KNOW.
THAT'S A SHORT
STACK.
THIS RIGHT HERE
IS BLUE CORN BATTER?
YES.
IT'S OUR HOMEMADE
BLUE CORN BATTER.
THESE ARE
READY TO GO.
GORGEOUS.
THE FLAVOR'S WONDERFUL.
THE TEXTURE'S REALLY NICE.
AND THEN THERE'S THE OFF-
THE-HOOK AMARETTO FRENCH TOAST.
NO QUESTION WHERE
THE NAME CAME FROM.
RIGHT. EXACTLY.
MADE FROM CHALLAH BREAD...
SO THICK IT'S GOTTA BE STEAMED
TO COOK IT THROUGH.
SO I'M GONNA
PUT THIS ON HERE,
AND IT'S GONNA
STEAM LIKE CUSTARD.
SO IT'S GONNA BE ALMOST
GOOEY IN THE CENTER?
ALMOST--IT'S A CUSTARD--
VERY, VERY CUSTARDLIKE.
NOW IF REAL MAPLE SYRUP
ISN'T EXPENSIVE ENOUGH,
WE'RE GONNA
USE ORGANIC.
IT'S REAL ORGANIC
MAPLE SYRUP--
HONEY, PECANS
AND BUTTER,
LIKE, ALL JUST
WHIPPED UP TOGETHER.
CAN I TRY SOME?
YEAH. I'LL GET YOU
A LITTLE SCOOP.
HE'S EATING BUTTER.
CAN YOU BELIEVE IT?
WOW.
SO IMAGINE THAT MELTED OVER
YOUR AMARETTO FRESH TOAST
WITH THE ORGANIC
MAPLE SYRUP AND THAT.
THAT'S JUST GOOD
BY ITSELF.
WELL--YOU SCARE ME.
YOU'RE EATIN' BUTTER
OUT OF YOUR HAND.
I JUST
WANTED TO TRY--
GET IT ON THERE.
I SAY PACK SOME
IN BETWEEN--
GET A NICE MELT
IN THERE.
THAT'S MONEY FRENCH TOAST.
I NEED A LITTLE BIT OF NONFAT
MILK IN THERE, LIKE HALF FULL.
AND IF THAT'S NOT
ENOUGH SUGAR FOR YA...
(funny voice)
YES, MASTER.
THANK YOU.
YOU CAN ALWAYS TOP IT OFF
WITH A SLICE
OF MEGAN'S MADE-FROM-SCRATCH
GERMAN CHOCOLATE CAKE.
YOU LIKE BAKING?
YEAH, I DO
ENJOY BAKING.
WHEN OTHER KIDS WERE
HAVING LEMONADE STANDS,
I HAD BAKE SALES--
SERIOUSLY.
OH, YOU MUST HAVE
BEEN ONE RICH KID.
LOOK AT THOSE THINGS.
PEOPLE ARE PILIN' IN
FOR EVERYTHING MEGAN'S BAKING,
LIKE MONSTER
CHOCOLATE CHIP COOKIES
OR WHATEVER SCONE SHE'S
DECIDED TO MAKE TODAY...
THEY'RE WONDERFUL, AND THERE'S
A DIFFERENT ONE EACH DAY.
(Guy) IT LOOKS
LIKE A SPACESHIP.
(Megan) YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA
FILL THIS ONE.
AND THAT'S A GOOD HEAPING
TEASPOON OF RASPBERRY.
I THINK
THAT IS HEAPING.
THAT IS LIGHT
AND FLAKY.
YEAH.
MY MOM WOULD
LOVE THIS.
OR HER MOUTH-PUCKERING
KEY LIME PIE.
NOW OF ALL THE PIES THAT I EAT,
WHICH I DON'T EAT A LOT OF PIES,
BUT OF THE ONES I LIKE TO EAT,
KEY LIME IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE.
THE CRUST IS HOMEMADE,
AND SO IS THE CUSTOM
KEY LIME FILLING.
BUT HOW'S
IT GONNA GET BIG?
COPIOUS AMOUNTS
OF WHIPPED CREAM.
COPIOUS AMOUNTS.
YEAH.
I'M JUST GONNA
POUR IT IN HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH.
PEOPLE DON'T
EVEN HAVE AN IDEA
THAT BEHIND THESE WALLS
OF CORNED BEEF HASH,
THERE LIES THIS
ARTISAN OF PIE.
I'M CATCHING ON.
THEY'RE
CATCHING ON TO ME.
THEY'RE STARTING
TO LEARN?
YEAH.
THAT'S SO GOOD.
WOW.
THAT IS...
...SUPER TART?
THAT IS TART.
YEAH.
I'VE HAD SOME
KEY LIME PIE,
BUT I GOTTA SAY THAT'S SOME
PRETTY MONEY KEY LIME PIE.
AWESOME.
HIGH-FIVE
ON YOUR PIE. NICE.
THIS IS PORTLAND.
FROM MEGAN'S
MADE-FROM-SCRATCH DESSERTS
TO COLLIN'S KILLER HASH....
THIS IS PROBABLY ONE OF THE MOST
GENUINE PLACES IN PORTLAND
TO COME TO EAT.
THE WHOLE WORLD IS BUZZING BY,
BUT THIS IS JUST
A VERY RELAXED, HOMEY,
COMFORTABLE, REAL ENVIRONMENT.
AND A SECOND HOME
FOR JUST ABOUT ANYTHING ELSE
YOU CAN THINK OF.
WHAT'S
THE ADDRESS HERE?
1212 NORTHWEST
GLISAN.
IF YOU HAVE RANDOM JUNK IN YOUR
GARAGE YOU'D LIKE TO SEND
THAT YOU THINK WOULD
LOOK GOOD ON THE WALLS,
SEND IT... PLEASE.
UP NEXT WE'RE
HEADING TO INDIANA
TO A RETRO SODA SHOP
FOR A TASTE OF THE PAST.
IT'S LIKE LIQUID LIFESAVER.
I'M HERE IN GOSHEN, INDIANA,
ABOUT 30 MILES SOUTH
OF SOUTH BEND,
YOU KNOW,
THE HOME OF NOTRE DAME.
SO I'M CRUISIN' THE MAIN DRAG,
AND I GOTTA CHECK OUT
THIS KILLER RETRO RIDE
AND THE SOUTH SIDE SODA SHOP
THAT GOES WITH IT.
YOU COME BACK
TO SOMETHING LIKE THIS,
AND IT'S LIKE GOING
BACK HOME AGAIN.
THEY TAKE WHAT'S OLD
AND MAKE IT NEW AGAIN.
PART SODA SHOP DATING
FROM THE '40s...
SO YOU JUST HAVE TO KIND
OF SMUSH IT DOWN ON THE SIDE.
AND PART DINER.
NUMBER EIGHT ON WHITE.
WHAT OWNERS NICK AND CHARITY
BOYD ARE SERVING UP HERE
IS A LOT MORE THAN NOSTALGIA.
THE FOOD'S DELICIOUS.
HOW IS IT?
IT'S GREAT.
THE PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
IS JUST FANTASTIC.
THAT'S QUITE
THE WORKOUT.
NOW IS THIS HOW
THEY DO IT IN PHILLY?
THIS IS, YES.
AMERICAN CHEESE?
IT'S A SWISS-
AMERICAN CHEESE.
SWISS AMERICAN.
IT GIVES IT A LITTLE
MORE OF A BITE.
WHAT'S REAL IMPORTANT
IS NOT TO BREAK THE HINGE
ON THE BACK
OF YOUR BUN.
NOT TO BREAK
THE HINGE.
THAT'S GOOD, NICK.
I THINK WHAT MAKES
THE DIFFERENCE IS THAT...
SHREDDER, SHREDDER, SHREDDER
WITH THE PAINT SCRAPER.
SAME KIND OF WORK
MAKING SPIRAL FRIES...
THOSE ARE
SOMETHIN' ELSE.
AND FAMILY RECIPES,
LIKE THE GRILLED
LIVERWURST AND BACON
CHARITY'S GRANDFATHER
JUST HAD TO HAVE.
BUT NICK MAY BE PROUDEST
OF THE SPECIALTY HE COOKS UP
DOWN HERE IN THE BASEMENT...
WELCOME
TO THE INNER SANCTUM.
ONE POT AT A TIME.
THE CHILI IS PROBABLY
THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
NICK'S CHILI WON THE AREA
COOK-OFF SEVEN TIMES.
SHOULD I TELL HIM ABOUT
THE YEAR WE DIDN'T WIN?
SURE.
UH, CHARITY AND I DIDN'T VOTE,
AND WE LOST BY ONE VOTE.
NO?
YEAH, YEAH.
SEE, THAT'LL
LEARN YOU, WON'T IT?
YEAH.
YOU WANT TO START
MAKING SOME CHILI?
NO, JUST SITTING DOWN HERE
TALKING ABOUT STYROFOAM CUPS.
SO WE GOT
THE GROUND BEEF.
AND ADD
SOME CELERY.
AND THEN WE CAN
ADD THE ONIONS.
THEN THROW IN SOME
GREEN PEPPERS.
WE ONLY RUN ONE
BURNER RIGHT NOW?
YOU CAN GO TO TWO.
LET'S FIRE IT UP.
GO TO TWO. IT'S GONNA
GET HOT DOWN HERE.
YEAH, I NOTICED
THAT WHEN YOU COOK,
YOU LIKE TO USE A FAIR
AMOUNT OF SPICES.
YEAH.
THAT'S HOW I KEEP
MY HAIR UP.
THERE'S SOME
CHILI POWDER.
GET SOME CUMIN.
NICE SMOKY FLAVOR
COMING OUT OF THE CUMIN.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
ALL THE SEASONINGS
TO THE TOMATO SAUCE
SO WHEN WE ADD
THAT TO THE MEAT,
IT GETS EVENLY
SPREAD OUT.
THAT'S CORRECT,
YES.
THIS IS A SPECIAL INGREDIENT
THAT I LIKE TO PUT INTO IT.
UM, I--
WHAT IS--
AND WHAT IS THAT?
UH, THAT'S SOMETHING I'D RATHER
JUST SORT OF KEEP TO MYSELF.
SEVEN YEARS
OF CHAMPIONSHIP CHILI
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA SHARE IT
WITH ME--I CAN UNDERSTAND.
BEANS GO IN FIRST.
OKAY, GO AHEAD
WITH THE SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE MIX THIS UP...
THAT'S LOOKING GOOD.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
LET THIS SIMMER
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR,
HOUR AND A HALF, RIGHT?
CORRECT, YEP.
AND GET A LOAD OF THE WAY
YOU CAN ORDER IT--
BY THE SUNDAE GLASS FULL--
NAMED FOR NO PARTICULAR REASON
FOR NICK'S HOMETOWN.
PHILLY CHILI.
IT'S GREAT.
EGG NOODLES, CHILI.
GOT OUR ONIONS,
SOME CHEESE ON TOP
AND SOME
SOUR CREAM ON TOP.
NOW HOW DO YOU GET
TO THE BOTTOM OF THAT?
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT'S
A HOME RUN, BUDDY.
THE ONIONS
AND THE CHEESE
AND THE COLD SOUR CREAM WITH
THE WARM CHILI AND NOODLES--
YEAH, I COULD GET THAT
BY THE BUCKET.
FROM A GUY WHO NEVER EXPECTED
TO BE COOKING ANYTHING
FOR ANYONE.
ALL RIGHT, BRUCE, COMING UP.
YOU SEE, NICK AND CHARITY
WERE ANTIQUE DEALERS
TILL HER FATHER
ASKED THEM TO HELP OUT
OPENING HIS RESTAURANT.
TWO YEARS LATER, THEY OWNED IT.
TWO DECADES LATER, THEY'VE
BECOME A LOCAL INSTITUTION.
YOU CAN ALWAYS SEE
NICK AND CHARITY.
THE PEOPLE WHO OWN IT, THEY'VE
GOT A VESTED INTEREST IN IT,
AND YOU KNOW THAT THEY'RE HERE.
THEY CARE ABOUT IT.
HERE YOU GO.
WE BUILD RELATIONSHIPS
WITH THE CUSTOMERS.
YOU KNOW, I STARTED WAITING
TABLES WHEN I WAS 3,
SO I WAS THE ANNOYING KID
BOUNCING AROUND ALL THE TABLES.
SO THEY'VE KNOWN ME FOR,
YOU KNOW, MY WHOLE LIFE.
SO IT'S FUN.
NUMBER EIGHT.
I'M IN TRAINING.
BUT IT'S MORE THAN JUST FUN
THAT DRAWS THE CROWDS.
THERE'S THE FOOD...
IT WAS MY GRANDPA'S FAVORITE--
THE GRILLED TENDERLOIN.
HE LOVED IT.
NICK'S OWN IDEAS OF WHAT
A DINER MENU OUGHT TO BE.
SHALLOTS?
I LIKE TO WORK
WITH SHALLOTS.
COCONUT MILK.
FOR COCONUT RICE.
WE'VE JUST TRIED TO DO SOMETHING
DIFFERENT, KEEP IT INTERESTING,
THINGS THAT WE WANT
TO EAT OURSELVES.
WELL, OF COURSE,
IN A DINER YOU NORMALLY KEEP
A WHOLE BUSHEL
OF MUSSELS AND CLAMS.
YOU DO IF YOU'RE MAKING THIS--
A NEW ENGLAND SEAFOOD FEAST
IN NORTHERN INDIANA.
OH, THE SMELL
COMING OFF OF THAT.
WE LOVE TO EAT IT.
IF IT DOESN'T SELL...
(Guy)
...WE TAKE IT HOME.
WE TAKE IT HOME,
YEAH.
I'M GONNA ADD
A CUP OF LARD.
NICK DOES
ALL HIS OWN BAKING, TOO...
YOU WANT TO PLAY
BOBBING FOR LARD?
YOU GO FIRST.
ROLLING OUT EVERYTHING,
FROM PIES TO PASTRIES
TO AN OFF-THE-HOOK SWEDISH
BREAD CALLED LIMPA,
FLAVORED WITH ORANGE PEEL.
OH, THERE I GOT
SOME OF THE ORANGE.
I'M A BREAD
JUNKIE, TOO.
THAT IS GREAT.
AND REMEMBER, THIS PLACE
IS ALSO A SODA SHOP.
SUNDAES, SODAS--
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG HERE.
THE SODA WATER REACTS
TO THE ICE CREAM.
THEY'RE MAKING FLOATS
FROM OLD-TIME CARBONATED DRINKS
CALLED PHOSPHATES,
ESPECIALLY A FLAVOR BIG
IN THE '50s CALLED GREEN RIVER.
THAT IS THE STRANGEST
THING I'VE EVER HAD.
YEAH.
AND PEOPLE KNOW
TO ORDER GREEN RIVER?
OH, YEAH, THEY LOVE IT,
LITTLE KIDS ESPECIALLY,
'CAUSE IT'S SO SWEET,
AND IT TURNS YOUR TONGUE
GREEN IF YOU DRINK ENOUGH.
NOT YET.
NO?
PRETTY MUCH IF YOU DRINK
THE SYRUP STRAIGHT IT WILL.
DO IT.
I'M NOT SHOOTIN' IT.
YEAH, DO IT.
NO.
I WILL.
WHAT, ARE WE GONNA HAVE
A SODA WATER CHASER?
I'M NOT SHOOTIN' IT.
OKAY.
I JUST DID IT.
OHH, IT'S HORRIBLE.
IT'S LIKE
LIQUID LIFESAVER.
OKAY, YOU MIGHT
WANT TO STEER CLEAR
OF THE GREEN RIVER SHOOTERS.
BUT FOLKS HERE KEEP COMING BACK
FOR THE FLOATS AND THE SUNDAES
AND THE WHOLE DINER MENU
DONE NICK'S WAY
AND THIS RETRO JOINT
THAT KEEPS PACKIN' 'EM IN.
KIND OF LIKE
A HOMECOMING, YOU KNOW?
THE FEELING OF HOME,
COMING BACK HOME.
I GIVE YOU PROPS.
YOU ARE THE MAN.
COMING UP, WE'RE HEADING
TO THE WINE COUNTRY
FOR RETRO, CALI-STYLE.
SUSHI-GRADE AHI--
THAT'S WHAT YOU ALWAYS FIND.
(Guy) TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN I THINK OF RETRO DRIVE-IN,
I THINK OF MIDWEST, EAST COAST,
BUT NAPA, CALIFORNIA?
WELCOME TO TAYLOR'S
AUTOMATIC REFRESHER.
(man) JOEL, YOUR MILK SHAKE'S
READY. MILK SHAKE FOR JOEL.
YOU DON'T COME THROUGH ST.
HELENA WITHOUT STOPPING HERE.
YOU DON'T?
NO.
THIS IS A MUST-STOP?
THIS IS A MUST-STOP.
A TINY TAKE-OUT JOINT THAT
STARTED BACK IN THE '40s
WITH PICNIC TABLE SEATING...
STEVE UP?
RIGHT HERE.
AND A PRETTY BASIC
DELIVERY SYSTEM.
MARK M. AND UMI,
YOUR ORDER'S READY.
I'LL HAVE
THE SWEET POTATO FRIES.
IT'S GOT ATMOSPHERE,
BUILT-IN FLAVOR.
(Guy) YEAH, BUILT-IN FLAVOR
ON THE WALLS.
THERE YOU ARE.
THANK YOU.
OWNERS JOEL AND DUNCAN GOTT
BOUGHT THE PLACE IN '99.
I HAD A DELI IN CALISTOGA
FOR ABOUT TEN YEARS.
SO WHEN WE TOOK THIS
PLACE OVER IN '99,
HAD A LOT OF FOOD EXPERIENCE,
KNEW WHAT WE WANTED TO DO,
WHAT WE LIKED TO EAT
AND HOW WE LIKE TO COOK.
JUST NEVER REALLY HAD
THE RESTAURANT FORMAT THIS IS
TO SERVE.
AND NOW THAT THEY DO,
THEY'RE CRANKING OUT STUFF
LIKE THE MISS KENTUCKY
CHICKEN SANDWICH...
I'VE NEVER HAD BETTER.
SWEET POTATO FRIES,
CALAMARI, AND GET THIS.
DEFINITELY OUR AHI BURGER IS ONE
OF OUR MOST SIGNATURE THINGS.
IT'S A GREAT
PIECE OF MEAT.
JUST WHAT YOU EXPECT
TO FIND AT ANY DRIVE-IN--
AN AHI BURGER--
YEAH, OF COURSE.
I MEAN, OUT HERE
IN THE WINE COUNTRY.
SUSHI-GRADE AHI--THAT'S WHAT
YOU ALWAYS FIND, RIGHT?
I AM IN IT--
I'M IN IT TO WIN IT.
I DON'T GET ENOUGH SUSHI ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I NEED MY SUSHI FIX.
WELL, HERE IT COMES.
I'M GONNA START OUT
WITH 4 OUNCES
OF HIGHEST GRADE-A AHI
BURGER, OR AHI TUNA.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA DROP THAT
IN A LITTLE SOY SAUCE BATH--
JUST A LITTLE SOMETHING
THAT'LL SEAR UP ON THE OUTSIDE,
CARAMELIZE
A TINY BIT.
WE'RE GONNA
COOK IT TO RARE.
THAT IS A SLAB
OF AHI.
WE GET OUR FISH
OUT OF SAN FRANCISCO.
WE GET IT DELIVERED
SIX DAYS A WEEK.
CHANCES ARE ANY TIME YOU GET ONE
IT WAS CAUGHT THIS MORNING.
THIS IS GONNA
GO ON AN EGG BUN.
A LITTLE WASABI-GINGER
MAYONNAISE ON HERE,
A LITTLE ASIAN
SLAW ON HERE.
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT--
AHI BURGER READY TO GO.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
IT'S WORKING.
THERE'S NOT ONE PART
OF THAT I DON'T LOVE.
ALL RIGHT.
I LIKE IT, GUY.
THAT IS REALLY--
I MEAN--THAT--
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT. WOULDN'T
YOU LOVE TO HAVE A BITE OF THAT?
THE CRUNCH OF THE SLAW
REALLY KIND OF HITS ME.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE HAVING
AN AHI TUNA SALAD IN THE BUN.
WE CAN JUST LEAVE NOW.
IT'S OVER. THANKS.
DO YOU JUST COMMUTE DOWN
HERE FOR THE AHI BURGER?
YEAH.
PRETTY
DARN CLOSE.
AND THIS BEING
THE NAPA VALLEY...
AND I'LL ALSO HAVE
A GLASS OF WINE--
CHARDONNAY.
...GLASSES OF DUCKHORN
SAUVIGNON BLANC.
DID YOU KEEP ANYTHING
FROM THE ORIGINAL MENU?
OH, FRIES,
PRETTY MUCH.
THE PLACE HAD ALWAYS
BEEN A BURGER JOINT...
(woman) OKAY,
SO WE HAVE A CHEESEBURGER,
ONION RINGS
AND A LARGE LEMONADE.
BUT IT'S A BURGER JOINT
WINE COUNTRY-STYLE.
WHAT IS THAT
MASTERPIECE?
THIS MONSTER
RIGHT HERE
IS A WESTERN BACON
BLUE RING BURGER,
PRETTY OBVIOUSLY NAMED,
'CAUSE YOU GOT THE BLUE CHEESE,
YOU GOT THE ONION RING,
AND YOU GOT THE BACON.
AND THAT'S
HOW IT'S PREPARED--
THAT THE BLUE CHEESE
SITS IN THIS CRADLE
OF FRIED
FRIENDSHIP?
YEAH.
YEAH, I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND DO THE WISCONSIN BURGER.
GRILLED MUSHROOM, BACON,
CHEDDAR, MAYO, BARBECUE SAUCE?
YEAH, BUT I'M ALL ABOUT
THE GRILLED MUSHROOMS.
THAT'S WHAT'S
DOING IT FOR YA?
IT'S ONE
OF OUR BEST.
WITH THE MUSHROOMS
AND THE CHEESE AND THE BACON
AND THE BARBECUE
SAUCE?
WE GOT SO MANY PEOPLE
ADDICTED TO THAT THING.
BUT THE KEY TO ANY BURGER IS
WHAT'S UNDER ALL THE TOPPINGS.
IT'S ALL NATURAL,
EXCLUSIVE TO CALIFORNIA.
IT'S RAISED
HORMONE-FREE.
THAT'S PREMIUM
BEEF, BABY.
NO FLATTOP. I SEE THE FLATTOP
WARMING THE BUNS,
AND I SEE THE FLATTOP
GETTING THE BACON,
BUT I SEE
THE CHAR GRILL--
IT BRINGS OUT
THE FLAVOR.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T GET
THOSE GREAT GRILL MARKS
UNLESS YOU
HAVE A GRILL.
LOOK WHAT'S
GOING ON HERE...
OH, YEAH,
WE LIKE THAT.
WHEN THIS THING IS COOKING
AND YOU CAN SEE THAT--
CAN YOU SEE THAT JUICE
COMING OFF OF THERE,
AND IT'S
DRIPPING DOWN.
IT'S ALMOST
VAPORIZING.
SO WE GOT A CROSS
BETWEEN GRILLING IT
AND ALMOST STEAMING IT
AT THE SAME TIME.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE GONNA
LOAD THE GOOD STUFF ON
TO TURN IT
INTO A WISCONSIN.
SHOW ME THE MAGIC.
BACON ON. GONNA ADD SOME
MUSHROOMS AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
ABOUT 60 SECONDS,
IT'LL BE MELTING DOWN.
BETTER GET SOME SOURDOUGH
READY AND GET OUR BREAD CUT.
AND THIS GOES
ON SOURDOUGH?
THIS GOES
ON SOURDOUGH.
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE GOT OUR HOMEMADE
OOEY BARBECUE SAUCE.
YOU MAKE
THE BARBECUE SAUCE?
SURE DO.
THERE WE GO. YOU HAVE
A THING ABOUT THIS V DEAL.
EVEN DISTRIBUTION. YOU WANT
EVERY BITE TO BE THE SAME.
THE LAST THING YOU WANT IS A BIG
PILE OF SAUCE IN THE MIDDLE,
SO YOU GOT ONE JUICY
BITE IN THE MIDDLE,
AND THEN IT'S ALL DRY
ON THE OUTSIDE.
RIGHT, RIGHT, OKAY.
THESE ARE EPIPHANIES
YOU HAVE?
JUST STANDING HERE COOKING
AND EATING ALL DAY LONG.
LOOK AT THAT
BAD BOY.
OKAY, HERE WE GO.
ARE YOU IN ON THIS?
YEAH,
I'M IN ON THIS.
OR YOU DON'T EAT
YOUR OWN FOOD?
NO, I'M IN ON THIS.
MM, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S WORKING FOR ME.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE QUALITY, HUH?
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT--
THE JUICE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY,
OTHER THAN
I NEED A NAPKIN.
UH-HUH.
BUT AS REAL DEAL
AS THE BURGERS ARE,
THIS PLACE AIN'T
A 1-TRICK PONY.
WHEN WE COME BACK, IT'S A NAPA
TAKE ON FISH AND CHIPS.
WHEN YOU'RE DRIVING THROUGH ST.
HELENA IN THE WINE COUNTRY,
TAYLOR'S AUTOMATIC
REFRESHER POPS UP
JUST LIKE IT DID
ALMOST 60 YEARS AGO.
AND I HEAR AT 10:30
IN THE MORNING
PEOPLE ARE STANDING IN LINE
LOOKING FOR CHEESEBURGERS.
IT DOES
HAPPEN, INDEED.
(Duncan) YAMASHITA,
YOUR ORDER'S READY, YAMASHITA.
THANK YOU.
BUT THIS RETRO TRIP
ISN'T JUST BURGERS.
YOU GOT YOUR DOGS.
IT'S A 1/4 POUND
ALL BEEF.
THAT'S A GOOD DOG.
SOMETIMES KNOWN
AS THE SHAKE BROTHERS HERE.
YOU GOT YOUR 1950s-STYLE
MILK SHAKES.
WE GO THROUGH A COUPLE
HUNDRED SHAKES A DAY.
IT'S CREAMY CHOCOLATE.
I'M A CHOCOHOLIC.
AND IN A CLASSIC
AMERICAN DRIVE-IN,
YOU'VE GOT ONE MORE
SIGNATURE ITEM.
FISH AND CHIPS.
YEAH, YOU HEARD IT RIGHT--
AMERICAN DRIVE-IN,
BRITISH FAVORITE.
YOU SEE 'EM IN ALL
DIFFERENT KINDS OF PLACES.
WHAT MAKES THEM
SO INTERESTING AT TAYLOR'S?
GOOD BATTER,
GOOD FRESH FISH.
THEY USE ONLY A-GRADE HALIBUT.
AND WHAT
ABOUT THE BATTER?
WHAT'S THE INTERESTING
FACTOR ON THE BATTER?
IT'S GOT ANCHOR STEAM
BEER IN THERE.
ANCHOR STEAM BEER--
A LOCAL
SAN FRANCISCO BEER...
YEAH, A LOCAL.
THAT'S BEEN HERE
FOR DECADES.
AND THE CARBONATION
HELPS THE BATTER BE NICE
AND LIGHT AND CRISPY
WHEN IT FRIES UP.
OOH, FISH IS READY.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
A LITTLE TARTAR.
A LITTLE SLAW
AND SOME LEMON.
HERE COMES THE FISH
READY FOR GUY.
WOW.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW DO YOU EAT A LOT
OF THE FISH AND CHIPS?
I DO EAT A LOT
OF FISH AND CHIPS.
REALLY?
I LIKE THAT.
IS THAT WORKING?
I LIKE THAT BATTER.
I LIKE THE BEER.
I TASTE THE BEER
IN THAT BATTER.
CAN I JUMP
IN THERE WITH YA?
OOH, YEAH,
IT'S STILL STEAMIN'.
I'VE GOT ALL THE FOOD GROUPS--
FAT, CRUNCH, BROWN AND YELLOW
AND, OF COURSE,
WHITE AND CHOCOLATE.
THIS IS OUR NEW FAVORITE SPOT.
AND IT'S BEEN THAT WAY SINCE
THE GOTT BROTHERS TOOK OVER.
WELL, WE SERVED 600 OR 700
PEOPLE THAT FIRST NIGHT.
SO DAY NUMBER TWO
WE WERE OUT OF FOOD.
WE PUT UP A SIGN THAT SAID
"WATER MAIN BROKE,"
AND WE CLOSED
FOR A DAY...
(Guy) NO?
WENT AND GOT MORE SUPPLIES
AND REOPENED ON SUNDAY.
IT WAS CLASSIC.
...SO CLASSIC
THIS DRIVE-IN ACTUALLY WON
A JAMES BEARD AWARD.
WHAT CATEGORY
DID YOU WIN IT IN?
AMERICAN CLASSIC.
AND THAT MEANS
THE BEST OF RETRO
AND THE BEST NEW TWIST
ON BASIC HOMEMADE COOKING...
TWO CHEESEBURGERS,
TWO FRIES.
A LEMONADE
AND A REGULAR COKE.
THE KIND OF PLACE WHERE
STANDING IN LINE
REALLY IS WORTH THE WAIT.
VERY GOOD.
HEY, I EAT HERE ABOUT
360 DAYS A YEAR.
I GOTTA MAKE SURE
IT'S ALL GOOD FOR ME.
EITHER YOU'RE WEARING A GIRDLE,
YOU RUN MARATHONS
OR YOU'RE
LYING TO ME.
A LITTLE BIT OF BOTH.
AND I DON'T SEE
ANY RUNNING SHOES.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
WE'LL SEE YA NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(imitating Mike Meyers)
WELCOME TO "COFFEE TALK."
I'M GUY, AND THESE
ARE MY FRIENDS.
I CAN'T
REMEMBER THEIR NAMES.