HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
IT'S ALL ABOUT BREAKFAST.
(woman) SOMEONE'S HUNGRY TODAY.
THE 80-YEAR-OLD JOINT
IN KENOSHA, WISCONSIN,
WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
THE GARBAGE PLATE.
(woman) EGGS,
HASH BROWNS, VEGGIE,
MEAT, CHEESE--
FABULOUS.
THE PLACE IN SAN PEDRO,
CALIFORNIA,
WHERE HOMEMADE ISN'T
JUST BIG, IT'S HUGE!
(Guy) HOLY MOLY!
AND THE NEVADA LANDMARK
WHERE YOU WON'T BELIEVE
HOW MANY EGGS THIS GUY
CAN CRACK AND HOW FAST.
MIGHT SET
THE RECORD HERE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
(Guy) I'M HERE
IN KENOSHA, WISCONSIN,
ABOUT AN HOUR NORTH OF CHICAGO,
AND JUST A FEW BLOCKS OFF
OF LAKE MICHIGAN
AT A PLACE WHERE THEIR BREAKFAST
SPECIAL IS CALLED
THE GARBAGE PLATE.
(woman) ALL RIGHT,
FULL PLATE, THREE MEATS.
SOMEONE'S HUNGRY TODAY.
HOW MUCH WILL YOU
BE ABLE TO PUT DOWN?
I'LL TRY FOR HALF,
BUT THE DOGS WILL GET THE REST.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN ANYBODY
EAT A FULL ONE?
NO, THIS IS A HALF.
HE HAD THE FULL.
THEY'RE GOIN'
FOR THE GARBAGE HERE
AND A TON OF OTHER
HOMEMADE FAVORITES...
ALL I NEED IS A SAUSAGE.
LIKE NONSTOP OMELETS,
FLUFFY SCRAMBLES
WITH A HUGE SLAB OF HAM,
AND FRENCH TOAST
MADE FROM FRESH-BAKED BREAD.
AT FRANK'S DINER...
WOW, THERE'S
A LOT OF PEOPLE
IN A LITTLE PLACE.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN
PACKIN' 'EM IN
AND ONE PIECE OF AMERICAN
FOR MY SCRAM, PLEASE.
JUST ABOUT FOREVER.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE
IN TOWN.
EVERYBODY KNOWS YOU.
OUT OF MY WAY!
THAT WAY.
THE DINER'S BEEN HERE
SINCE 1926,
WHEN IT WAS PULLED TO THE SITE
BY A TEAM OF HORSES.
OWNER ANTHONY FRANK'S KIDS
HAVE BEEN TELLING THE STORY
FOR YEARS.
IT WAS QUITE A BIG EVENT
WHEN IT CAME INTO TOWN.
THE STREET WAS FULL
OF PEOPLE
WAITING FOR THIS STRANGE
CAR TO COME TO KENOSHA.
AND OVER THE DECADES,
THIS PLACE HAS BECOME
A LOCAL LANDMARK.
IT'S KIND OF
A FAMILY TRADITION.
MY GRANDPARENTS USED
TO HANG OUT HERE,
MY PARENTS HANG OUT HERE,
AND NOW I HANG OUT HERE.
SIX YEARS AGO WHEN
THE FAMILY DECIDED TO SELL,
A COUPLE OF SURPRISED BUYERS
WITH NO EXPERIENCE
IN THE FOOD BIZ
DECIDED TO TAKE A CHANCE...
TOMATO, LYNNY.
CHRIS SCHWARTZ
AND LYNN GROLEAU.
(Guy) AND THIS,
I THINK, SAYS "FRANK'S"?
(Chris) IT SAYS
"FRANK'S."
WHY DID YOU KEEP
THE NAME?
THAT'S PART
OF HISTORY.
THAT'S IT?
OH, YEAH.
DID YOU COME HERE
BEFORE YOU BOUGHT IT?
OH, YEAH,
WE WERE REGULARS.
AND THEN YOU HEARD IT WAS
FOR SALE AND YOU SAID.
"ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL GO LOOK AT IT."
AND AFTER A COUPLE
BOTTLES OF WINE AND...
(man laughs)
TAKING A LOOK
AT THE PLACE,
THERE WE GO.
(Lynn) COUPLE BOTTLES
OF WINE?
THAT'S NICE TO DO
AT 7:00 a.m.
YOU BELIEVE THAT STORY?
IF MY DAD WERE AROUND,
HE'D BE SO PROUD OF THEM.
NEITHER OF THEM--THEY HAD
NO RESTAURANT EXPERIENCE
UNTIL THEY CAME IN HERE.
WATCH A MASTER
ON THE GRILL.
YES. YES.
LOOKS LIKE SHE'S BEEN COOKIN'
FOR 40 YEARS THIS WAY.
HEY, ARE YOU SAYIN'
I'M 40 YEARS OLD?
NO, I WAS GONNA SAY YOU
WERE BORN AT THE GRILL.
YOU LOOK LIKE A SEASONED
LINE COOK OF 30 YEARS.
PUTTIN' OUT DOZENS OF
HOME-COOKED ORDERS AT A TIME...
READY ON ONE.
LIKE PANCAKES WITH
PEANUT BUTTER AND JELLY,
CINNAMON ROLL FRENCH TOAST,
A RUBEN OMELET
WITH THOUSAND ISLAND DRESSING
AND THE FAMOUS GARBAGE PLATE...
YOU THINK YOU CAN
PUT THAT ALL DOWN?
YEAH.
A HUNK OF HASH BROWNS WITH
WHATEVER'S IN THE KITCHEN
SCRAMBLED UP WITH EGGS
FOR $8.95.
SO GARBAGE PLATE'S
THE NUMBER-ONE HEAVY HITTER.
GARBAGE PLATE'S NUMBER-ONE
HEAVY HITTER.
UNQUESTIONABLY, THAT'S--
THAT'S IT.
MAKE MORE OF THOSE
THAN ANYTHING IN A DAY.
SO EVERY GARBAGE PLATE
STARTS THE SAME WAY?
ONIONS, THE GREEN
BELL PEPPER,
THE JALAPEÑO.
YEP. CHORIZO.
CHORIZO, THAT'S INTERESTING.
I MEAN, I'M IN CALIFORNIA,
AND WE HAVE
A LOT OF CHORIZO.
IS CHORIZO BIG UP
HERE IN--
NO, I MEAN,
I MEAN, IN KENOSHA
RIGHT BY THE WATER?
IT CAN BE.
THESE ARE ALL MY
GARBAGE PLATES.
OF COURSE, NO ONE CAN ORDER
THEM THE SAME WAY,
SO THAT'S WHY I HAVE 18 OF THEM
ON THE GRILL ALL DIFFERENT.
BUT WE ARE HERE
TO ACCOMMODATE
AND TO PLEASE.
SOMEONE CAN REALLY EAT
THAT WHOLE THING?
OR IS THAT, LIKE,
A FAMILY GETS THAT?
THIS IS FOR ONE GUY
WAY ON THE END.
THIS IS YOURS?
THAT'S MINE..
2-MEAT GARBAGE PLATE?
HAVE YOU HAD THIS BEFORE?
I HAVE.
CAN YOU EAT
THIS WHOLE THING?
NO.
YOU HAVE ALREADY
SUBDIVIDED YOURS.
I'M WORKIN' THIS WAY.
IT HAS ALL THE MEAT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT REALLY IS.
AND USUALLY,
I DON'T EVEN LIKE EGGS.
I KNOW.
THIS IS THE MOST EGGS
YOU'VE EVER SEEN ME EAT.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO HEAR
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I MEAN, IT'S JUST
REGULAR BREAKFAST STUFF
BUT THERE'S
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
I THINK THE CHORIZO.
WHOO-EE.
NOW YOU DON'T HAVE
TO GO FOR THE GARBAGE.
LOTS OF FOLKS COME HERE
FOR THE OMELETS
OR THE HUGE FRENCH TOAST.
THIS IS ALL FOR YOU?
I THOUGHT I'D SHARE SOME...
OH, MY GOODNESS!
WITH A FRIEND
IN THE BACK DINING ROOM.
YOU GONNA SHARE WITH ME?
NO? THAT WAS NO?
CAN'T BLAME HER--
THE FRENCH TOAST COMES
FROM HOMEMADE BREAD.
NEVER EXPECTED THIS
FROM A BREAKFAST JOINT.
WE WANTED TO STAY
WITH THE TRADITION
OF OLD DINER,
EVERYTHING HOMEMADE,
EVERYTHING MADE TO ORDER, AND
HOMEMADE BREAD IS PART OF THAT.
THEY SCRATCH-BAKE
EVERYTHING HERE.
WE HAND-KNEAD
THE BREAD.
I HAD THE MOST ARM POWER,
SO I GOT STUCK DOING IT.
LET ME SO THOSE
HEATERS, HUH?
LOO--OH, MY--
OKAY, WE'RE NOT ARM
WRESTLING FOR FOOD.
DO YOU KNOW HOW TO BRAID?
YOU'VE GOT IT.
NO, I JUST WANTED TO--
(Chris) MAKE IT PRETTY?
WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS.
I DON'T WANT YOU TO SAY,
"OH, HEY, MARGE, LLOYD.
"HEY, HOW YOU DOIN'?
GUY FROM THE FOOD NETWORK
MADE THAT JERKY ONE."
NOW THAT--THAT'S GOOD
FOR A FIRST TRY.
I'M IMPRESSED.
AND AS LONG AS WE'RE
IN THE BACK ROOM BAKING,
GET A LOAD OF THIS.
THESE ARE THE PASTIES.
NOW WHERE DID YOU LEARN
TO MAKE PASTIES?
UM, THIS IS A GRANDMOTHER
AND A MOTHER THING.
SO, UM--
ARE PASTIES BIG HERE
IN LOWER WISCONSIN,
UPPER ILLINOIS?
A LITTLE BIT,
BECAUSE A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE
COME FROM UPPER MICHIGAN,
AND THAT'S WHERE
THESE COME FROM.
IT'S KIND OF
A MIDWEST EMPANADA...
THIN AS YOU CAN
POSSIBLY GET IT.
STUFFED WITH BEEF
AND ALL KINDS OF VEGETABLES.
PUT HER IN THE DOUGH,
MAKE YOUR LITTLE HALF MOON,
AND YOU'RE DONE.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
I COULD EAT ANOTHER
SIX OF THOSE.
IT'S AWESOME.
I'M SEEIN' THE LIGHT.
MMM.
CAN I TRY.
EVERYTHING HERE'S
THE KIND OF HOMEMADE FOOD
YOU MIGHT NOT WANT TO SHARE.
WHAT? SOUP?
YEAH, GO AHEAD.
UH... YEAH, YOU READY?
BUT AS KILLER AS THE FOOD IS,
THE FEEL OF THE PLACE
IS AS BIG AN ATTRACTION.
"ORDER WHAT YOU WANT.
EAT WHAT YOU GET."
I LIKE THAT.
YOU LIKE THAT?
CAN I GET A CUP OF COFFEE?
GO GET IT YOURSELF.
OKAY.
(laughter)
DOES EVERY--
JUST BECAUSE YOU LIKE ME,
OR DOES EVERYBODY GET
TREATED THAT WAY?
EVERYBODY DOES
THAT WAY.
SERIOUSLY?
AND IF YOU'RE GONNA
DO YOUR OWN REFILL,
YOU'RE GONNA REFILL THE ENTIRE
DINER, NOT JUST YOU.
NO.
UH, YEAH.
YOU JUST PICK
IT UP AND GO?
YOU HAVE TO.
YOU DON'T HAVE A CHOICE.
HALF A CUP?
NO, PUT IT
ALL IN THERE.
ANY REAL RHYME
OF WHO GOES WHERE.
DO YOU GET, LIKE,
SECTIONS, OR--
IT'S, UM, IT'S
ORGANIZED CHAOS.
OKAY.
YEAH.
WORK OKAY?
WANT SOME MORE COFFEE?
OKAY, GO GET
IT YOURSELF.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE PLACES
WHERE EVERYBODY KNOWS YOUR NAME.
...AND HAS FOR EIGHT DECADES.
WE DO OUR BEST, SINCE IT'S
81 YEARS OLD, OKAY?
WHICH MAKES FRANK'S THE OLDEST
CONTINUALLY OPERATING
LUNCH CART DINER IN THE U.S.,
PRESERVING A TRADITION--
GREAT FOOD AND GREAT TIMES.
TO HAVE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
IS KIND OF A TREASURE.
YOU WORK SIX DAYS A WEEK?
PRETTY MUCH, YEAH.
RIGHT LIKE THIS?
RIGHT LIKE THIS,
SO I'M ON THIS--
SHE DOES THE BACK KITCHEN,
I DO THE FRONT KITCHEN.
I MEAN, IS IT A LITTLE
STRANGE THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE
IN KENOSHA
KNOW YOUR BACKSIDE?
PEOPLE WANT TO ADVERTISE
BACK THERE, THOUGH.
YEAH, I'M TELLIN' YA.
I'M THINKIN' ABOUT--
LET ME GET
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
UP NEXT, THE CALIFORNIA JOINT
THAT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE MUCH
BUT TURNS OUT BREAKFASTS
THAT LOOK LIKE THIS.
WHEN ROLLIN' THROUGH SAN PEDRO
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA,
CLOSE TO ONE OF THE BUSIEST
PORTS IN THE COUNTRY,
YOU MIGHT JUST BLOW BY A PLACE
LIKE THE GAFFEY STREET DINER.
BUT THAT'D BE A SHAME,
'CAUSE WHAT'S GOIN' ON INSIDE
IS WAY BEYOND
WHAT YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND
IN THE AVERAGE
WORKIN' MAN'S DINER.
(Guy) HOLY MOLY.
THEY'RE WHIPPIN' UP BREAKFAST
LIKE THE FRENCH TOAST SUPREME.
THIS IS THE SUPREME.
SUPREME CUBED?
ALL THE FOOD I'VE HAD HERE
IS DELICIOUS.
PANCAKES FILLED
WITH FRESH BLUEBERRIES...
YOU PUT THE BLUE
IN BLUEBERRY, GIRL.
EGGS BENEDICT
WITH FRESH HOLLANDAISE
AND A HAM STEAK
THE SIZE OF A CAR.
THAT'S THE HAM
FOR THE EGGS BENEDICT?
YEAH.
THE PTERODACTYL
EGGS BE--
I MEAN, LOOK AT
THE SIZE OF THAT HAM!
USUALLY CANADIAN BACON
SLICES, LIKE, YOU KNOW--
YEAH, THEY'RE TOO LITTLE.
YEAH.
IT'S A LOT OF FOOD, TOO.
(Guy) THAT IS
A LOT OF FOOD.
AND THAT'S NOT, LIKE,
A LITTLE SKIMP.
I GOTTA TALK TO HER ABOUT
FOOD COSTS--WE HAVE ISSUES.
SO THERE'S OUR BACON.
BACON'S DONE.
FOR BARBARA ZEMEDIES AND HER
PARTNER IN LIFE AND BUSINESS,
CHEF RUDY, GOOD ENOUGH
JUST ISN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
(Barbara) HOMEMADE
TOMATILLO SAUCE.
THE HOLLANDAISE--
YOU MAKE THIS EVERY DAY?
YEAH, EVERY SINGLE DAY.
200 POUNDS? WHO PEELS
ALL THE POTATOES?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
FRESH ORANGE JUICE.
TWO CASES EVERY DAY.
I'M JUST WORKIN' HIM
TO DEATH.
AND THAT MEANS SCRATCH-COOKING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
I LIKE IT FRESH.
WHERE'D YOU
FIND THIS GUY?
THAT'S WHERE WE MET AT
IS THE RESTAURANT.
HE WAS THE COOK.
I WAS THE WAITRESS.
AND WE STARTED GOING
OUT TOGETHER.
YOU SWEPT HIM
OFF HIS FEET.
YES, I DID.
WE BOTH DID.
NOW THEY'VE GOT A JOINT
OF THEIR OWN.
I COME HERE EVERY DAY.
EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
IF I CAME HERE
EVERY DAY,
THEY'D HAVE TO WHEEL ME
OUT IN A CART.
AND WHY NOT?
WHAT THEY'RE DOIN'
REALLY IS REAL HOME COOKIN'.
AH, THIS SMELLS GOOD.
DO WE BUY ANYTHING
PROCESSED?
WELL, WE TRY NOT TO.
(man)
THE CHEESE?
THE BREAD.
OH, REALLY, SO WE'RE
NOT MAKING THE CHEESE?
OH, WELL.
THEY TRIED ONE TIME,
BUT IT DIDN'T WORK OUT.
THE GOAT AND THE COW
WERE MAKING TOO MUCH
NOISE IN THE BACK.
YOU GOT HERE
AT WHAT TIME?
I'M HERE AT 3:30
IN THE MORNING.
3:30 IN THE MORNING.
THAT'S GOOD. THAT'S GOOD.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF MY CLOCK HAS 3:30.
3:30 IN THE MORNING--
MAKE THE POTATOES,
BOIL THE POTATOES,
PEEL THE POTATOES,
MAKE THE CHILI VERDE,
MAKE THE SALSA,
MAKE THE HOLLANDAISE,
MAKE THE--
WHAT ELSE DO YOU GOT
OVER THERE?
OH, THESE ARE
THE BISCUITS.
HE'S WAITING FOR
THE DOUGH TO RISE.
WE HAVE OUR
BISCUITS OVER HERE.
WOW, SO THAT--I MEAN,
THAT'S THE SIZE OF A BASEBALL.
BISCUITS ARE READY.
(whistles)
WE GOTTA PUT THE SAUSAGE.
WOW, YOU REALLY DO
PUT THE SAUSAGE.
IT'S TENDER.
IT'S FLUFFY.
NICE CRUNCH--
IT'S NOT TOO DRY.
YOU KNOW, A LOT OF TIMES
YOU GET BISCUITS SO DRY--
IT'S BECAUSE YOU
MAKE 'EM EVERY DAY,
AND THEY DON'T SIT.
THEY'RE NOT JUST WARMED UP.
RIGHT OUT OF THE OVEN.
WOW.
(man) THE GRAVY'S
EXCELLENT.
THE HOMEMADE BISCUITS
ARE AWESOME.
OKAY, YOU GOT MY EGGS FOR
THE CHICKEN FRIED, BABE?
THEY'RE SOME OF THE HARDEST
WORKIN' FOLKS
IN THE FOOD BUSINESS.
IT'S HOMEMADE.
IT'S HOME.
EVEN--HE MAKES
THE CHORIZO HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE.
YOU MAKE THE CHORIZO?
UH-HUH.
I CAN'T HANDLE ANY MORE.
I'M EMOTIONALLY
ON THE EDGE RIGHT NOW.
YOU MAKE THE CHORIZO?
I MAKE THE CHORIZO.
THAT IS SOME BOMB CHORIZO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DO YOU LIKE IT?
DO I LIKE IT?
MM-HMM.
MY FRIEND,
THAT IS SOME
OF THE BEST CHORIZO--
I MEAN, I FEEL
LIKE I'M MAKING THIS UP,
BUT THAT IS--
YOU MAKE IT?
YEAH, I MAKE
IT MYSELF.
AND WAIT TILL YOU SEE
HOW HE POACHES THE EGGS.
THERE'S PICKLES IN THE WATER
FOR THE POACHING?
YES, OF COURSE.
IS THAT FOR
THE VINEGAR FACTOR?
YEAH.
THAT TIGHTENS IT UP?
I MEAN, YOU COULD ADD
A LITTLE BIT, BUT THE PICKLE?
MM-HMM.
THAT IS BANANAS.
WE HAVE THE COOKING
PROCESS--
THERE WAS FOUR--FIVE--FIVE
DIFFERENT COOKING PROCESSES
THAT HAVE GONE ON JUST
TO COOK ONE DISH.
CUT AND GRILLED THE HAM,
POACHED THE PICKLE-
POACHED EGGS,
THE FRIES--THEY HAD TO
COOK THE POTATO FIRST,
THEN PEEL IT, THEN THEY
MAKE THE HOLLANDAISE,
AND PUT IT
ON TOP OF THAT.
FOR $7.95, I GOTTA
TELL YOU SOMETHING--
THAT'S HANDS-DOWN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS.
(bell rings)
I GOT AN ORDER
FOR MENUDO.
WE HAVE A TICKET
YES.
WHAT IS MENUDO?
I MEAN, I KNOW WHAT IT IS,
BUT GIVE ME
THE BIG DESCRIPTION OF IT.
OKAY, MENUDO IS A TYPICAL
MEXICAN SOUP
THAT PEOPLE LIKE TO EAT
WHEN THEY HAVE HANGOVERS.
IT HAS BEEF FEET,
AND THEN IT--
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT--
BEEF FEET?
YES, THE FOOT OF THE COW.
HIS FEET. HIS HOOVES.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THAT WAS
STEPPING IN THE WHOLE TIME?
OH, BUT THEY'RE
NICE AND CLEAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT
THIS IS FOR?
THIS IS FOR HANGOVERS.
SO I'VE HEARD.
ARE YOU HUNG OVER, SIR?
NOT AT THE MOMENT.
BUT YOU'RE WILLING TO LEARN.
THAT'S NOT THE ONLY HANGOVER
REMEDY THEY'VE GOT.
I LIKE THE JOHN WAYNE BREAKFAST.
IT'S GREAT FOR HANGOVERS.
I'VE GOT TWO JOHN WAYNES.
TO JOHN WAYNES,
EXTRA CHEESE.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S A JOHN WAYNE.
TELL ME THE STORY
ABOUT THE JOHN WAYNE.
OKAY.
WHEN RUDY WORKED IN REDONDO
BEACH, ONE DAY,
JOHN WAYNE WENT IN THERE,
AND THEN HE TOLD JOE,
"JOE, JUST GIVE ME SOMETHIN'
THAT'S GONNA GET RID
OF THIS HANGOVER."
SO THEN THEY CAME UP
WITH THE JOHN WAYNE--
HOME FRIES ON TOP,
EGGS ON TOP,
CHEESE ON TOP,
COVERED WITH
SPANISH SAUCE,
AND SURROUNDED
BY SAUSAGES.
LIKE THE WAGONS.
WE NEED A COUPLE HAND CARTS
TO WHEEL THESE GUYS OUT.
IT'S LIKE SUPER CHEF
AND WONDER WOMAN.
(giggles)
WHAT'S GREAT TO SEE
IS TWO PEOPLE GETTING
SUCH SATISFACTION
BY MAKING GREAT FOOD...
IT TASTES
LIKE IT'S HOMEMADE.
SO MANY PEOPLE LOVE.
OVER THE YEARS,
I'VE SWITCHED UP
DIFFERENT PLACES,
AND I'VE FOUND GAFFEY STREET
DINER, AND I HAVEN'T LEFT.
(Guy) AND YOU
HAVEN'T LEFT.
I LOVE THEIR FOOD HERE.
I LOVE THEIR SERVICE HERE.
EVERYTHING IS EXCELLENT.
WE HAVE TWO DAYS
OFF A YEAR.
DO YOU REALLY?
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THOSE?
CHRISTMAS,
THANKSGIVING.
LAUNDRY AND DUSTING?
CHRISTMAS.
CHRISTMAS AND THANKSGIVING
WHEN WE CLOSE.
WELL, I COULD JUST SEE.
IF YOU'D GIVE HIM A CHANCE,
HE'D BE OPEN TWICE
ON NEW YEAR'S.
NEXT UP, WE'RE
IN BOULDER CITY, NEVADA,
WITH SOME KILLER CHILI VERDE...
(Guy) THAT'S THE SAUCE.
AND THE FASTEST EGG MAN
IN THE WEST.
HE'S IN A RHYTHM.
(Guy) WHEN I WENT TO COLLEGE
DOWN THE ROAD IN LAS VEGAS,
I DROVE THROUGH BOULDER CITY
PROBABLY A HUNDRED TIMES.
WELL, LITTLE DID I KNOW, IT'S
THE HOME OF THE COFFEE CUP CAFé.
IT'S BEEN HERE FOR 75 YEARS,
HELPED FEED ALL THE GUYS
WHILE THEY WERE BUILDIN'
THE HOOVER DAM,
AND THE CHILI VERDE IS THE BOMB.
IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S GREAT
ON HUEVOS, MAN.
ON HUEVOS RANCHEROS,
AN OMELET,
THE HOMEMADE GREEN CHILI
IS KILLER.
SO ARE ALL THE OTHER OMELETS
WITH HOMEMADE BEEF CHILI,
SPINACH, ONIONS AND TOMATOES.
OR THE FRENCH TOAST...
IT'S THE BEST AROUND.
OR PANCAKES OR WAFFLES.
I'M HAVING
THE CHOCOLATE CHIP,
AND IT'S SCRUMPTIOUS.
PEANUT BUTTER WAFFLES
ARE WORTH ANY DRIVE.
I GOT MY SON EATIN' EM, TOO,
SO I CAN GET HALF OF HIS.
THE CUP'S HOME TO EVERYBODY.
HOW'S IT GOIN'?
BEATIN' ALL THE CROWDS TODAY?
I EAT A LOT.
AND YOU RODE OVER HERE
ON BICYCLES?
MOTORCYCLE.
OH, MOTORCYCLE.
BICYCLES?!
YOU LOOK LIKE YOU WERE
PROBABLY BORN ON A BIKE.
I TRAVEL A LOT, SO THIS
KIND OF--IT'S BECOME HOME.
ALL THE WAY FROM PARIS
TO EAT HERE.
$2.70, $2.70...
WE TRY AND KEEP IT DOWN SO
THAT PEOPLE WILL COME BACK.
WE DON'T WANT IT
TO BE A ONCE-ER.
SWITCH.
CARRI AND AL STEVENS
BOUGHT THE CUP 12 YEARS AGO.
'KAY, BYE.
NICE SEEING YOU.
DID YOU GUYS MOVE?
THEY RUN IT WITH THEIR
DAUGHTER LINDSAY.
AND SOME HONEY.
HONEY.
I'M RIGHT HERE.
AL WAS IN RESTAURANT SUPPLY.
CARRI HAD BEEN A WAITRESS.
DID THEY ALREADY GET
YOUR DRINKS FOR YOU?
BUT THEY'D NEVER RUN A PLACE
TILL THEY FOUND OUT THEIR
FAVORITE JOINT
WITH A 70-YEAR HISTORY
WAS SUDDENLY ON THE MARKET.
WE DIDN'T HAVE A LOT
OF TIME TO THINK ABOUT IT.
I HEARD IT WAS KIND OF
LIKE A FIRE SALE,
LIKE A BOOM, BOOM,
WE GOTTA DO IT NOW.
YEAH, IT WAS, LIKE, ON
A MONDAY WE TALKED ABOUT IT,
BY THURSDAY WE HAD IT.
BUT WHEN WE BOUGHT
THE RESTAURANT IN TWO DAYS,
THIS IS WHO WE BOUGHT
THE RESTAURANT FROM.
REALLY? LOOK AT THE SMILES
ON THEIR FACES.
YES, WE'RE
STILL SMILING.
I DIDN'T TELL THEM WHEN
THEY CALLED YESTERDAY
TO SAY THE WERE COMING--
I DIDN'T TELL THEM
YOU GUYS WERE GONNA BE HERE.
OH, YOU SET THEM UP?
I DID SET THEM UP, YES,
'CAUSE I KNEW
THAT IF THEY KNEW THAT...
OH, THIS IS GOOD.
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE
SHOWED UP.
LET ME TELL YOU
ABOUT THE NEXT CAFé
I'M GONNA SELL YA.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET HER
ON YOUR BAD SIDE, AL.
NOT AT ALL.
LOOK AT AL.
JUST OVER THERE BY THE REGISTER,
JUST, "DON'T LOOK AT ME."
DAD EVER WAIT TABLES?
NO.
NO? WHAT'S HE DO A LOT?
GETS FIRED.
GETS FIRED?
HE FIRES HIMSELF?
WE FIRE HIM ALL THE TIME.
I FIRE HIM EVERY DAY.
LITTLE TOO MUCH
ATTITUDE SOMETIMES.
(Guy) OH, THAT'S THE SAUCE.
HE DOES GET THE CREDIT
FOR A SIGNATURE DISH.
I AM A PORK CHILI
VERDE MACHINE.
BASICALLY, YOU'RE GONNA
START OFF WITH PORK--
DICED.
WHO'D HAVE THOUGHT?
HEAD COOK JOE HERMAN'S
MAKING GALLONS A WEEK
FROM AL'S ORIGINAL RECIPE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DRAIN OFF
THIS PORK JUICE.
OKAY.
IT'LL BE USED
IN A GREEN CHILI SAUCE
OR OTHER DISHES.
WE'LL SAVE THAT FOR LATER.
WILL I GET INVITED
TO THE HOLIDAY PARTY NOW?
YOU'RE ON, MAN.
YOU ARE HERE.
AM I?
GOOD, I'M EXPECTING--
YOU'RE ON THE LIST.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
SOME ACTUAL GREEN CHILIES.
YEP.
CILANTRO GOES IN.
HERE COMES
CAPTAIN JALAPEÑO.
WIELDS THAT KNIFE
LIKE A SAMURAI WARRIOR.
I'M WORRIED RIGHT NOW, BOY.
THIS IS WHERE
THE GUESSWORK COMES IN,
'CAUSE IT COULD
BE ON FIRE, OR--
WELL, YOU NEVER KNOW
WITH THE JALAPEÑOS
HOW IT'S GONNA GO.
ADD A LITTLE SPICE.
WOW, HOW MUCH
OF THAT'S GOIN' IN?
WE USE THE "SWAG" SYSTEM HERE,
IF YOU'VE HEARD ABOUT THAT--
SIMPLY THE WILD
(beep) GUESS.
THOS BIG CHUNKS--AND YOU CAN
SEE THAT JALAPEÑO IN THERE
AND THE GREEN CHILIES.
BET YOU THIS IS
GONNA BE HOT.
IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
I THINK THAT SHOULD BE
SERVED IN A SANDWICH.
WE MAY HAVE TO JUST MAKE
THAT JUST FOR YOU.
IT'S A BIG HIT
IN AN OMELET.
I THINK IT SHOULD SAY, YOU KNOW,
"WELCOME TO BOULDER CITY.
TODAY WE HAVE
THE CHILI VERDE OMELET."
(Al) WE DO SPANISH OMELETS
ALL FROM SCRATCH--
ALL THE VEGETABLES--
COUNTRY OMELETS WITH GRAVY
AND TATERS AND COUNTRY
GRAVY--
TATERS?
YEAH.
YOU SOUND LIKE
A RESTAURATEUR NOW.
WHAT ARE WE LOOKIN'
FOR NOW?
JUST THE HASH BROWNS.
SOME HASH BROWNS.
THE GUY BEHIND THE OMELET
IS HEAD COOK JOE...
THAT'S A MEAL,
BROTHER.
WHO'S A PRIZED COMMODITY
IN THE BREAKFAST BIZ--
A FIRST-RATE EGG MAN. ..
THIS IS YOUR GO-TO
BURGER OVER HERE, ISN'T IT?
YES, IT IS.
A VEGAS VETERAN WHO'S
A WIZARD WITH A SKILLET.
HOW MANY OMELETS CAN YOU
TURN OUT IN TEN MINUTES?
IN TEN MINUTES WITH,
UH, SIX PANS?
PROBABLY ABOUT 18,
MAYBE.
6 PANS, 10 MINUTES--
18?
18.
NOW I'VE ALSO HEARD
THE LEGEND--
THE RUMOR OUT
ON THE STREET
THAT YOU CAN DO 180 EGGS
IN 180 SECONDS.
YES, I CAN.
I'VE GOTTA PUT THIS
TO THE TEST WHEN WE COME BACK.
THIS IS LIKE EVEL KNIEVEL
JUMPIN' THE GRAND CANYON.
ON YOUR MARK.
GET SET...
COME HERE. THIS IS
THE BEST FOOD IN TOWN.
WHERE YOU CAN JUST
SIT AND ENJOY
AND THEY DON'T TRY
TO KICK YOU OUT TOO SOON.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
WE COME HERE
EVERY WEEKEND.
FOR YOU?
WE'RE HANGIN' OUT AT THE COFFEE
CUP IN BOULDER CITY, NEVADA...
IT'S SCRUMPTIOUS.
HOME OF THE KILLER
PORK CHILI VERDE,
AND APPARENTLY THE FASTEST
EGG CRACKER IN THE WEST.
(Guy) SO GET READY.
HERE'S JOE HERMAN--
180 EGGS IN 180 SECONDS.
ON YOUR MARK...
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
EGGS BACK ON THE CARTON.
NO JUMPIN' THE GUN.
I MEAN, THAT'S LIKE HAVIN'
YOUR FOOT OVER THE LINE.
TIMER ARE YOU READY?
YEAH.
ON YOUR MARK...
GET SET...
GO!
HOW MANY SECONDS?
OH, MAN, HE'S IN
A RHYTHM RIGHT NOW.
HE'S IN A RHYTHM--OOH!
I MISSED ONE.
GO, JOE,
YOU'RE DOIN' GREAT.
YOU MIGHT SET
THE RECORD HERE.
AS THE TIMER
READS IT RIGHT NOW,
HE'S ONE EGG BEHIND.
I WOULD STILL BE ON
CARTON ONE RIGHT NOW.
THIS GUY IS A MACHINE.
SPOTTED HIM
A COUPLE EGGS.
TWO STRAGGLERS.
DIDN'T MAKE IT.
THREE MINUTES
AND TEN SECONDS.
NICE JOB!
YEAH, JOEY!
OKAY, SO HE'S TEN SECONDS OVER.
BUT COULD YOU DO THAT?
MY BROTHER--MONEY.
NOW JOE DOES MORE
THAN EGGS AND BREAKFAST.
I HAVE A BACON BURGER.
THE CUP STAYS OPEN
FOR THE LUNCH CROWD, TOO,
WITH MORE HOMEMADE FAVORITES,
LIKE A CHICKEN, CHEESE, BACON
AND GREEN CHILI SANDWICH.
THERE'S A GREAT TURKEY MELT,
A CLASSIC BURGER,
AND AN OPEN-FACE SHREDDED
ROAST BEEF SANDWICH...
LOOK AT THAT!
FROM A ROAST THAT'S BEEN
SLOW-COOKING FOR HOURS
AND HOURS.
3:00 IN THE AFTERNOON
TO ABOUT 6:00.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT JUST FALLS APART.
OH, YEAH.
THEY'RE ALSO BIG
ON THE MEATLOAF HERE.
THE SECRET--POUND THE HECK OUT
OF IT AND GET THE AIR OUT.
I WAS THE BISCUIT AND MEATLOAF
MAKER WHEN I WAS LITTLE.
WELL, WHAT MAKES
GOOD MEATLOAF?
WHEN I MAKE IT.
BUT IT'S THAT PERSONAL
ATTENTION
FROM THE WHOLE FAMILY
THAT MAKES THE COFFEE
CUP WHAT IT IS...
I'M THE ORCHESTRA LEADER.
I GO, "OVER THERE.
"OVER HERE. OVER HERE."
AND HE IS THAT WAY.
THE BEST OF WHAT IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN SINCE THE 1930s.
(Al) I ENJOY THE PEOPLE.
I ENJOY THE COOKING.
UH, A LOT OF CHARACTERS,
YOU KNOW, IN THE KITCHEN,
A LOT--A LOT OF
CHARACTER CUSTOMERS.
JUST WONDERFUL PEOPLE.
IS IT WHAT YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS GONNA BE?
I THINK IT'S, UH,
BETTER THAN WHAT I THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE. IT'S FUN.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO CHASE DOWN.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
FROM THE LAKE.
BWAH.
ALL RIGHT, FLOUR.
NO! NO!
DON'T EVEN START!
I HAVE GOT SO MUCH MORE.