HI, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADIN' FOR SOME
OF AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP, A NEW TWIST
ON THE BLUE PLATE SPECIAL--
SIGNATURE DISHES
FROM COAST TO COAST,
LIKE THE GREEN JOINT
ON THE PACIFIC
WHERE THEIR SO-CAL BREAKFAST
WILL HAVE YOU SAYING
"I'LL BE BACK..."
ARNOLD PUT THIS
ON THE MENU?
ARNOLD WANTED IT
ON THE MENU.
THE CHICAGO DRIVE-IN
WHERE THEY'RE HOME COOKIN'
SOME OFF-THE-HOOK ITALIAN BEEF,
AND THE CHARLOTTE LANDMARK
WITH THE BLUE PLATE PICKLE.
ONE OF THE BEST FRIED PICKLES
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
WHEN I'M CRUISING
THROUGH A BEACH TOWN
ANYWHERE IN AMERICA,
I COME ACROSS
THESE FUNKY LITTLE PLACES
THAT MAKE ME ASK,
IS IT A TOURIST TRAP,
OR DO THE LOCALS
REALLY EAT THERE?
SO I'M ON PACIFIC COAST HIGHWAY
BETWEEN SANTA MONICA AND MALIBU
WHEN I COME ACROSS THIS JOINT--
PATRICK'S ROADHOUSE.
I JUST GOTTA PULL IN AND SAY,
"HEY, SO WHAT'S THE STORY?"
WELCOME TO PATRICK'S.
THE STORY IS A LOCAL LEGEND.
(man) WE'VE BEEN HERE
FOR 33 YEARS.
A FORMER RAILWAY STATION
TURNED RESTAURANT...
THIS IS THE LEGENDARY
BREAKFAST PLACE.
RUN BY A GUY WHO MOVED HERE
FROM PORTUGAL...
I SPEAK A LITTLE ENGLISH...
YOU SPEAK A LITTLE...
GERMAN...
SO DO I.
WITH A WAITRESS FROM BRAZIL...
WELL, LOOK
AT THE SMILING SERVICE
YOU HAVE RIGHT HERE.
HUH?
THE CUSTOMERS--
I LOVE THEM.
EVERY WEEKEND,
I'M HERE.
AND A FIERCELY LOYAL
CALIFORNIA CLIENTELE...
THE BEST.
IN LOVE WITH A MENU
OF HOMEMADE FAVORITES...
THIS IS MY KITCHEN.
LIKE FRESH CHICKEN SALAD,
AN OVERSTUFFED
BREAKFAST SANDWICH,
SOMETHING CALLED
EGGS FLORENTINOVICH
WITH JACK CHEESE, OLIVES,
MUSHROOMS AND FRESH SPINACH...
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND THE OWNER'S
SPECIAL CREATION...
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING OMELET.
CALLED SILVIO'S OMELET,
WITH SILVIO'S SECRET...
I DON'T THINK I WOULD HAVE DONE
THE ONIONS THAT WAY...
ONIONS CARAMELIZED
IN BROWN SUGAR...
BUT I LIKE 'EM IN THERE.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
AND A HUGE BREAKFAST
THAT MADE IT ONTO THE MENU
AS KIND OF A BLUE PLATE SPECIAL
FOR ONE OF THE REGULARS.
ARNOLD USED TO COME IN
EVERY DAY.
RIGHT.
AND THERE'S ONE DISH
THAT HIS MOM ALWAYS MADE
IN AUSTRIA.
WHICH WAS THIS?
WHICH WAS
THE BAUERNFRUHSTUCK, KIND OF.
YOU KNOW, YOU CHOP EVERYTHING UP
THAT YOU HAVE AROUND...
OKAY.
AND YOU JUST PUT IT TOGETHER.
SO IT'S REALLY EVERYTHING
FROM THE KITCHEN,
THE GARDEN, THE BARN...
A LITTLE CUMIN,
NOT TOO MUCH,
YOU CAN OVER--
ARNOLD PUT THIS
ON THE MENU?
ARNOLD WANTED IT
ON THE MENU.
REALLY?
YEAH.
SAUSAGE.
WE MAKE A GOOD TEAM,
SILVIO.
YOU JUST KEEP BRINGING IT
OVER HERE.
A LITTLE BACON.
THEN WE SHOULD HAVE
A LITTLE HAM.
HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU SELL, NORMALLY?
EGGS?
OR BAUERNFRUHSTUCK?
FARGENBRUGERS.
MANY.
THERE WE GO.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE SPICE.
I LIKE THAT.
THE BAUERNFRUHSTUCK
WAS ALREADY ON THE MENU
WHEN SILVIO STARTED
AS A NEW WAITER HERE IN 1989,
A RECENT IMMIGRANT
FROM PORTUGAL
WHO NEEDED A JOB AND CONVINCED
OWNER BILL FISCHLER
TO GIVE HIM A SHOT...
SO THAT'S BILL.
NOT THE FIRST SNAP DECISION
BILL HAD MADE.
JUST ASK HIS SON HOW BILL
BOUGHT THE PLACE TO START WITH.
IN THOSE DAYS
THIS WAS CALLED ROY'S,
AND IT WAS JUST THIS
LITTLE BUILDING RIGHT HERE.
LITTLE PART, RIGHT.
AND MY FATHER ORDERS HIS BURGER,
TAKES ONE BITE OF HIS BURGER,
AND JUST REVOLTED BY IT,
TURNS TO HER AND SAYS,
"HOW CAN YOU SERVE
THIS GARBAGE?"
(laughs)
AND ROY--IT'S THE END
OF THE DAY--
ROY'S GOING, "LOOK, WHY DON'T
YOU BUY THE PLACE?"
AND THE NEXT DAY MY FATHER
WAS IN HERE FLIPPING BURGERS.
SO EVERYTHING
STAYED THE SAME.
I MEAN, THERE'S
ALL THESE FUNNY LITTLE THINGS,
LIKE THIS LITTLE SWITCH,
AND I...
DON'T PULL THAT ONE,
'CAUSE THE WHOLE ROOF
WILL COME DOWN.
EVERYTHING WILL
FALL OFF.
THE COUNTER IS THE SAME COUNTER.
THE TABLES ARE THE SAME TABLES.
THIS WAS
THE ORIGINAL COUNTER?
YES.
THAT CUP MAY HAVE BEEN HERE
FOR THE LAST 35 YEARS.
AND THEN RING--
(bell dinging)
KINDA...
GOD, THAT'S LOUD!
AFTER BILL PASSED AWAY,
HIS FAMILY TURNED TO SILVIO.
TWO?
HE'S BEEN RUNNING THE PLACE
FOR TWO YEARS NOW...
CAREFUL, THE SYRUP IS HOT.
DOING THINGS BILL'S WAY.
WE'RE GONNA FOLLOW
BILL'S TRADITION
AND BILL'S BELIEFS
AND BILL'S DESIRES...
THAT'S BILL.
IF FLICKERING LIGHTS ARE A SIGN
THAT BILL'S WATCHIN',
HE'S GOTTA LOVE THE FACT
THAT SILVIO'S STILL GIVING
THE REGULARS
WHAT THEY'VE
BEEN LOVING FOR YEARS...
YOU ALWAYS ORDER
A PANCAKE.
'CAUSE I THINK
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT STRANGE,
AND WE LIKE THAT.
LIKE THIS SIGNATURE DISH
YOU WON'T FIND ANYWHERE ELSE.
WHY WOULD YOU EVER CHANGE
THINGS LIKE--
THE DIJON PLUMBURGER.
DIJON PLUMBURGER'S GREAT.
OKAY.
ANGUS BURGERS?
ANGUS BURGERS.
IS THAT MAYONNAISE
YOU'RE BUTTERING ON THERE?
YES.
OKAY, SO YOU'RE PUTTING
MAYONNAISE ON--
USUALLY, JUST A SMIDGEON.
A WHAT?
A SMIDGEON--
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO SAY SMIDGEON?
YOU JUST DON'T HEAR MANY PEOPLE
OFTEN USE THAT, YOU KNOW,
THAT ARE OUR AGE.
WE TAKE PLUM JELLY.
NOW WHO ORDERS THIS ONE?
CRAZY PEOPLE.
BUT DO PEOPLE LIKE IT
WHEN THEY ORDER IT?
GOOD CRAZY PEOPLE. YES.
THEY COME BACK AND HAVE IT.
SO PICKLES, TOMATOES...
LETTUCE.
THE BURGER--DID WE PUT SALT
AND PEPPER ON THE BURGER?
DIJON MUSTARD.
UH-UH.
YEAH, THAT'S ACTUALLY...
THAT'S THE SALT?
THAT'S THE SALT.
THE SEASON SALT?
THE SEASON SALT.
GOT IT.
PICKLE.
ALL OF IT.
HEY, HEY!
WHERE YOU GOING?
OH, OH, OH,
YOU'RE GONNA TASTE IT.
THIS IS WHAT
THIS IS ALL ABOUT.
DO YOU THINK
I'M GONNA LIKE IT OR NOT?
I THINK YOU'RE GONNA LIKE IT.
YOU'VE GOT GOOD TASTE.
DO YOU THINK I COULD
PUT HALF OF IT IN MY MOUTH?
I'LL BET YOU 5 BUCKS
THAT YOU CAN'T.
THAT RIGHT THERE, SERIOUSLY--
I'D HAVE THAT
OUT ON THE STREET.
"COME TRY
THE PLUM DIJON BURGER."
WOW, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
BUT IF YOU THINK THAT'S WEIRD,
CHECK OUT THIS ONE.
THE ROCKEFELLER BURGER
HAS MUSHROOMS, JACK CHEESE.
SOUR CREAM GOES ON HERE.
AND THEN THE CAVIAR...
AND THEN THE CAVIAR.
GOES ON TOP OF THAT.
CORRECT.
WOW. THAT'S CRAZY.
I'VE NEVER--I MEAN,
I'VE SEEN A LOT OF THINGS. I
DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN THAT.
GO FOR IT.
WOW.
DIFFERENT, HUH?
YEAH.
WHILE SILVIO'S KEPT
EVERYTHING THAT'S BEEN
ON THE MENU FOR YEARS,
HE HAS STARTED BRINGING IN
SOME NEW STUFF, TOO...
CHICKEN OR SALMON
MANGO SALAD--
LIKE FRESH ORGANIC PRODUCE.
NOW YOU GO DOWN
AND PICK OUT ALL THE PRODUCE
DOWN AT THE MARKET?
CORRECT.
WHAT TIME DO YOU HAVE
TO GO DOWN THERE IN THE MORNING?
5:30 IN THE MORNING
I GET UP.
IT'S THE BEST GRILL IN TOWN.
I LOVE IT.
WHATEVER HE'S MAKIN'--
FROM FRUIT TO THAT
BAUERNFRUHSTUCK THING...
WOW.
SILVIO'S KEEPING THIS PLACE
AS REAL AS IT'S ALWAYS BEEN...
AND I PLAN TO BE HERE
FOR THE NEXT 30, 40 YEARS.
YOU COME IN HERE
AND YOU IMMEDIATELY FEEL
THAT YOU'RE HOME.
FOR FIRST-TIMERS...
OH, I'D LOVE TO COME BACK
AND BRING FRIENDS.
AND LONG-TIMERS...
I'VE BEEN COMING
TO PATRICK'S ROADHOUSE
FOR, I THINK, 25 YEARS.
AT THE GREEN JOINT ON PCH.
HOW WAS BREAKFAST?
EXCELLENT.
ENJOY YOURSELVES?
THANK YOU.
YEAH.
IT'S JUST BEEN
A GREAT EXPERIENCE.
COMING UP, WE'RE GOING
BACK IN TIME IN CHICAGO
FOR SHAKES, SUNDAES...
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
AND THIS JOINT'S
HUGE BLUE PLATE SPECIAL.
I HAVE SO MUCH IN MY MOUTH,
I CAN'T EVEN TELL YOU
HOW GOOD IT IS.
♪♪
ON THE SOUTH SIDE OF CHICAGO,
THERE'S A FEW THINGS
YOU CAN EXPECT TO FIND--
A TON OF WHITE SOX FANS,
GREAT ETHNIC FOOD
AND ONE OF THE LAST
TRADITIONAL DRIVE-INS
IN CHI-TOWN--
THE FROSTED MUG.
GOTTA WALK FAST
IF YOU WANT TIPS.
WITH CARHOPS
IN CHEERLEADER OUTFITS...
UNLESS THERE'S ABOUT 3 FEET
OF SNOW OUT,
THEN WE KIND OF GIVE
A LITTLE LEEWAY IN--
THEN YOU GET
TO WEAR GALOSHES.
HERE YOU GO.
A TIME-TESTED
SERVICE SYSTEM...
IF YOU'RE ORDERING OF IF YOU'RE
DONE, YOU TURN YOUR LIGHTS ON.
YES.
AND FRESH MADE ROOT BEER...
(woman) IT TASTES
A LOT COLDER.
THAT REALLY IS SERVED
IN FROSTED MUGS.
PULL!
THIS PLACE IS A TOTAL TRIP
BACK IN TIME.
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S THE MONEY POUCH?
YES.
OH, MAN, IF THEY COULD
SEE ME NOW.
IT GOES--
I CAN'T EVEN SEE
THE QUARTERS.
(man) WE CALL IT NOSTALGIA,
BUT IT'S PART
OF THE FABRIC OF AMERICA.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
RIGHT NOW YOU'RE IN
A LITTLE PIECE OF AMERICANA,
AND THAT'S WHAT WE--
WE KINDA FANCY IT--
OUR OWN LITTLE PIECE
OF AMERICAN HISTORY.
CONEY DOG, NO ONIONS.
CUSTOMERS ARE SO FANATIC
ABOUT THIS PLACE,
THEY CALL THEMSELVES
MUGGERS...
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
EVERYTHING'S MADE TO ORDER,
SO IT'S NOT SITTING AROUND,
LIKE, YOU KNOW, YOUR--
A CHAIN RESTAURANT.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND THEY CROWD THE JOINT...
ORDER, PLEASE, I NEED
A CHEESEBURGER...
FOR A MENU THAT RANGES
FROM BURGERS AND DOGS
TO ITALIAN BEEF
AND CAJUN CHICKEN.
MEDIUM CHOCOLATE SHAKE.
BUT FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
THE DRAW IS THE ICE CREAM.
I HAVE COMPLETELY
JACKED THAT ONE UP.
THERE YOU GO.
WOULD SOMEONE PAY
FOR THAT, REALLY?
UM, SURE.
NOW WHAT'S THE BELLY BUSTER?
THE BELLY BUSTER
IS A 32-OUNCE SUNDAE
WE PUT INSIDE OF A GLASS.
AND THIS IS ONE
OF THE MOST POPULAR?
YES,
BECAUSE IT'S MADE
WITH THE NATURAL STRAWBERRIES.
ALWAYS TOP IT
WITH WHIPPED CREAM, NUTS,
CHERRY AND A COOKIE.
WOW. TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT.
THEY MAKE THEIR SHAKES
WITH REAL FRUIT, TOO,
AND IN A TOTAL STEP BACK
IN TIME, REAL ROOT BEER FLOATS.
DO YOU EAT A ROOT BEER FLOAT
OR DRINK A ROOT BEER FLOAT?
BOTH.
IS IT SUPPOSED TO HAVE
BUBBLES LIKE THAT?
YES.
LOOKS LIKE A HOT TUB
NOT WORKING RIGHT.
GO AHEAD. IT'S DELICIOUS.
WOW. I HAVEN'T HAD
ONE OF THOSE IN A WHILE.
OH, MY SON HUNTER
WOULD GO BANANAS FOR THIS.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU EVER MAKE THIS
WITH SPLENDA?
THE ROOT BEER'S ACTUALLY MIXED
UP DOWN IN THE BASEMENT...
I'M GONNA TURN THIS
RIGHT HERE.
ON ANCIENT EQUIPMENT
OWNER JIM MONACO'S
KEEPING ALIVE.
AND THAT GOES
INTO A CARBONATOR...
OKAY.
AND THEN IT'S PUMPED
TO OUR REFRIGERATION SYSTEM,
AND THEN IT GOES UP.
INTO THE TAP.
INTO THE TAP--
THE DRAFT SYSTEM.
BUT YOU GOTTA HAVE
A FROSTED MUG.
GOTTA HAVE A NICE FROSTED MUG
LIKE THIS.
YOU PULLED A BEER BEFORE,
I'M SURE.
OH, YEAH.
BUT IT ISN'T
JUST THE SWEET STUFF
THAT DRAWS THE CROWDS.
IN THIS PLACE,
THEY'RE COOKIN'--REALLY!
THIS ISN'T JUST FAST FOOD.
THIS IS PREPARED FOOD.
IT'S A RESTAURANT.
WITH HOMEMADE MINESTRONE SOUP,
CHICKEN PARMESAN,
REAL SLOPPY JOES,
CAJUN GRILLED CHICKEN
AND, OF COURSE,
THE FRESH-MADE BURGERS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE LIKE
TO ORDER THE TEXAS BURGER.
THAT'S ONE
OF OUR FAMOUS BURGERS.
WE'RE IN CHICAGO.
THEY ORDER
THE TEXAS BURGER.
THEY DO, BECAUSE--
THAT MAKES NO SENSE.
WELL, IT'S 1/2-POUND BURGER
ON A TRIPLE BUN,
AND PEOPLE LIKE THAT BECAUSE
IT'S A GOOD, HEARTY BURGER.
OKAY, AND WHAT SAUCE
COMES ON THAT?
SPECIAL SAUCE, LETTUCE, PICKLE,
CONEY SAUCE, ONIONS AND CHEESE.
WOW.
AND THE BLUE PLATE SPECIAL
AT THIS PLACE
IS HOMEMADE ITALIAN BEEF,
SEASONED THEN SLOW COOKED
IN A PIZZA OVEN.
OKAY.
IT'S JIM'S FAMILY RECIPE.
(Jim) WE SLICE IT MEDIUM RARE,
THIN AS YOU CAN.
AND WE THROW IT
RIGHT INTO THE AU JUS,
WHICH IS RUNNIN' OVER
AT 160 DEGREES,
(Guy) SO IT BRINGS IT
UP TO TEMPERATURE.
BRINGS IT
RIGHT UP TO TEMP.
IT WENT FROM PINK
TO PERFECT.
HUH?
SOME SWEET PEPPERS,
LIKE THAT.
OKAY.
OH.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SHOT
IN THE STEAMER.
GIVE IT JUST A LITTLE KISS.
JUST GIVE IT A LITTLE...
HOW MUCH IS THIS?
THAT'S $4.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
YEAH.
OH, YEAH. I HAVE
SO MUCH IN MY MOUTH,
I CAN'T EVEN TELL YOU
HOW GOOD IT IS.
IF THAT'S NOT ENOUGH,
THERE'S THE COMBO,
WITH ITALIAN BEEF ON TOP
OF ITALIAN SAUSAGE
AND PEPPERS AND CHEESE.
(Jim) A PIECE
OF MOZZARELLA.
(Guy) NICE FACIAL.
THIS I THINK YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO SIT DOWN AND EAT.
IT'S GONNA GET MESSY,
ISN'T IT?
YEAH.
I'M GOING IN.
HOT. HOT.
REALLY SUPER HOT.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
CAN YOU FINISH
THE WHOLE THING?
TWO OF 'EM.
NO.
SURE, IF I WANT.
SERIOUSLY?
SURE.
HOW TALL ARE YOU, 6'4"?
I'M A SEASONED--
YEAH, RIGHT AROUND THERE.
YEAH, YOU KNOW, GIVE OR TAKE.
JUST DEPENDS IF IT'S
A COLD DAY OR NOT.
SEASONED VETERAN--
WHEN YOU'VE HAD TO HAVE EATEN
A HUNDRED OF THESE THINGS--
A HUNDRED HERE, A HUNDRED
THERE--FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
THE MUGS THE PLACE THAT'S
ALWAYS BEEN HERE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN COMING HERE?
ABOUT 20 YEARS.
THERE'S A REAL SENSE THAT IT
ALWAYS OUGHT TO BE...
SINCE I WAS LITTLE. I COME UP
AND BRING MY KIDS NOW.
A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT...
IT'S GOOD FRIENDS, AND WE LIKE
THE PEOPLE THAT ARE HERE.
LOCAL KIDS AS CAR HOPS,
A MENU THAT NEVER CHANGES
AND AN EXPERIENCE
THAT NEVER CHANGES EITHER.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
HERE'S YOUR LARGE HOT FUDGE
SUNDAE, NO CHERRY.
YOU SEE, WHEREVER YOU'RE GOING
IN SOUTH CHICAGO SINCE 1962,
IT'S BEEN KIND OF A HABIT
TO STOP AT THE MUG.
(Guy) SO WHERE ARE WE GONNA GO
AFTER THIS?
I'M FREE FOR THE REST
OF THE DAY.
WE'RE GOING SHOPPING.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO COME WITH US?
DEPENDS ON WHERE WE'RE GOING.
COMING UP, WE'RE GOING
TO THE PENGUIN
IN CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA,
WHERE A TATTOOED CHEF...
THE MORE HOMEMADE STUFF
WE CAN DO, I THINK, THE BETTER.
IS KEEPING FAMILIES HAPPY...
HOW GOOD IS THE HOT DOG?
WITH HIS BLUE PLATE SPECIAL
OF DEEP-FRIED PICKLES.
THE BEST FRIED PICKLES
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
IF YOU REALLY WANT TO FIND OUT
IF SOMEONE IS FROM CHARLOTTE,
NORTH CAROLINA,
THEN ASK 'EM
WHERE THE PENGUIN IS.
IF THEY SEND YOU TO THE ZOO,
THEN YOU KNOW
THAT THEY AIN'T FROM HERE,
'CAUSE THE PENGUIN
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT
HAS BEEN ROCKIN' IT
FOR OVER 50 YEARS,
MAKIN' SOME OF THE MEANEST
PICKLES YOU'LL EVER TRY.
FRIED PICKLE, FRIED PICKLE,
FRIED PICKLE.
YOU FEELIN' GOOD
ON THOSE, BOSS?
(man) YEP.
YOU HEARD ME.
THEY'RE FRYING PICKLES...
HALF PICKLE
TO THE WINDOW.
AND THE CROWD'S GOING WILD.
DEFINITELY
THE BEST FRIED PICKLES
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
THEY'VE GOT ALL KINDS
OF GREAT STUFF HERE--
HUGE BURGERS,
HAND-DIPPED CORN DOGS,
EVEN A GRILLED BANANA
AND PEANUT BUTTER SANDWICH.
HERE YOU GO, BOO.
TAKE A BITE.
BUT WHEN YOU'RE TALKIN'
OFF-THE-HOOK
BLUE PLATE SPECIALS
WHAT COULD
BEAT DEEP-FRIED PICKLES.
EVERY DAY,
PROBABLY 90% OF THE TABLES
HAVE FRIED PICKLES ON 'EM.
CHEF GREG AUTEN STARTED OUT
AT HIS DAD'S CONCESSION STAND
AT THE FAIR.
SINCE THEN HE'S WORKED
AT PLENTY
OF FINE-DINING RESTAURANTS
AND COME UP WITH PLENTY
OF RECIPES.
BUT THE FRIED PICKLES
MAY BE HIS BIGGEST HIT YET.
DO YOU THINK, IN THE WORLD
OF DEEP-FRIED PICKLES,
YOU'RE DOING IT THE BEST?
I MEAN, YOU THINK YOU'RE PUTTING
THE BEST SPIN ON IT?
YEAH, I THINK SO,
'CAUSE IT'S PRETTY SIMPLE.
SO YOU JUST HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF SEASONED FLOUR THERE.
THOSE HAVE BEEN
IN THE BUTTERMILK
FOR A COUPLE HOURS.
SHAKE THE EXTRA FLOUR OFF.
SHAKE OFF THE EXTRA.
DON'T WANT TO KILL
THE FRYER OIL
YEP, JUST DROP 'EM
RIGHT IN THERE.
NOW, THESE FRY UP
PRETTY QUICK?
MM-HMM.
IT TAKES ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
ANY SALT ON 'EM?
NOPE. THEY JUST GO
LIKE THEY ARE.
THINK I CAN PICK UP
A LITTLE PART-TIME GIG HERE?
OH, YEAH.
QUALITY CONTROL.
WOW.
I DON'T LIKE PICKLES AT ALL,
AND I TRIED THE FRIED PICKLES--
AND I CAN'T GET
ENOUGH OF THEM.
THE PICKLES ARE PRETTY RECENT,
BUT THE PENGUIN'S
BEEN AROUND SINCE 1954
AS YOUR BASIC BURGER JOINT.
WHEN IT WENT UP FOR SALE
EIGHT YEARS AGO,
LOOK WHO ENDED UP BUYING IT.
SO GIVE ME THE STORY
ABOUT HOW YOU TWO CAME ALONG
TO FIND THIS PLACE
AND THEN BRING THE CHEF IN.
WE WERE JUST GONNA DO A BAR,
AND 'CAUSE OF ZONING THEY SAID
YOU HAVE TO HAVE FOOD.
AND THE GUY CATERED MY WEDDING,
MY BUDDY HERE,
SO I CALLED HIM UP THAT NIGHT.
I SAID YOU WANT TO JOIN A TEAM?
LET'S OPEN A BAR AND RESTAURANT.
AND HERE WE ARE--
THAT'S A FUNNY PHONE CALL. "HEY,
BUDDY! YOU CATERED MY WEDDING,
AND WE'RE GONNA GET THIS PLACE
AND DO IT."
AND THEY DID IT, RENOVATING
THE PLACE AND THE MENU.
AND NOW LOOK WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN THEY OPEN THE DOOR.
IT'S KINDA LIKE
GOING TO BUMPER CARS.
WHEN YOU GET THERE YOU'RE
WAITING IN LINE THE WHOLE TIME.
WHEN YOU FINALLY DO,
YOU RUN TO THE CAR YOU WANT.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY
RESTAURATEURS
WOULD KILL TO OPEN THEIR DOOR
ON A SUNDAY MORNING
AND HAVE THE PLACE
GO IMMEDIATELY TO PACKED?
IT'S GREAT.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE EVER
IN CHARLOTTE.
FOLKS SAY THEY'RE WILLING
TO LINE UP HERE
'CAUSE WHAT THEY GET
IS MORE THAN FAST FOOD,
IT'S THE REAL DEAL...
THE MORE HOMEMADE STUFF
WE CAN DO, I THINK, THE BETTER.
LIKE A SOUTHERN FAVORITE
FEW PEOPLE BOTHER
TO MAKE
FROM SCRATCH ANYMORE.
(Guy) PIMENTO CHEESE IS ONE
OF YOUR BLUE PLATE SPECIALS.
WHAT WAS THE INSPIRATION
BEHIND THE PIMENTO CHEESE?
I GREW UP
EATING PIMENTO CHEESE.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S BIG THING
HERE IN THE SOUTH.
CHEDDAR CHEESE.
5 POUNDS
OF CHEDDAR CHEESE.
AND THEN THE--
JALAPEÑO JACK.
AND YOU GOTTA HAVE THIS COLD
SO IT'LL MIX UP RIGHT.
OTHERWISE IT'LL BE CLUMPS
OF THIS AND CLUMPS OF THAT.
YEAH, IT'S REAL HARD TO MIX
ONCE IT STARTS GETTING WARM.
THE JUICE PLAYS A BIG PART
IN THE PIMENTOS HERE.
YOU GET A NICE PIMENTO FLAVOR
FROM THE JUICE.
ROUND OUT THE SEASONING
WITH GARLIC,
CAYENNE AND BLACK PEPPER.
THEN MIX IT UP
WITH A LITTLE MAYO.
IT'S 3 CUPS OF MAYO, SO--
THIS IS MY MEASURING STYLE
RIGHT HERE. 1 CUP--
YEP, THAT'S IT.
EYEBALL IT.
AH, THAT'S GOOD.
THANK YOU.
THAT REINSPIRES ME
TO MAKE THAT AGAIN.
I USED TO MAKE
THAT WHEN I WAS IN COLLEGE.
YEAH?
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA.
I THINK IF PEOPLE TRY THIS,
I DON'T THINK
THEY WOULD EVER HAVE
A REGULAR
GRILLED CHEESE AGAIN.
IT AIN'T JUST PIMENTO CHEESE.
GREG'S BIG
ON ALL KINDS OF STUFF
YOU NEVER FIND
BEING MADE FROM SCRATCH.
TRY NOT TO HAVE
ANY AIR HOLES.
JUST WORK 'EM AROUND
AND PULL IT OUT.
TWIST IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA RUN
TO THE FRYER
RIGHT NOW.
YOU NEVER THINK THAT THEY'RE
REALLY MAKING THE CORN DOG.
(Greg) RIGHT.
IT'S ALL PREFROZEN,
YOU KNOW, JUNK.
BY FAR THE BEST WAY
I'VE FOUND TO DO IT
AND IT'S REALLY THE ONLY WAY
I WANTED TO DO IT.
(mumbling)
THAT'S GOOD.
I'M GLAD I LET IT
COOL DOWN.
(Greg laughs)
IT'S ONLY A SECOND-DEGREE BURN
RIGHT NOW.
(laughs)
MMM.
I'M TELLIN' YA. THERE IS
A NICE SWEETNESS DOWN THERE.
GOOD CORNMEAL--I MEAN,
YOU CAN ACTUALLY TASTE
THE CORNMEALY FLAVOR
TO IT,
NICE CRUNCH.
THEY GOT A WHOLE MENU
OF KILLER DOGS,
LIKE THE RACE TRACK DOG
WITH SLAW AND CHILI
OR THE WINKY DINK DOG
WITH CHILI AND PIMENTO CHEESE.
(Guy) HOW GOOD
IS THE HOT DOG?
I THINK I'LL TRY WHIPPING UP
A CREATION OF MY OWN--
(Guy) YOU KNOW WHERE
I'M GOING WITH THIS?
(Greg) I KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING.
A CORNDOG STUFFED
WITH PIMENTO CHEESE AND BACON--
MONEY.
WOW.
WHERE DO YOU WANT TO GO?
IN THE BASKET?
HO, HO! HUH?
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK IT THERE.
A LITTLE BACON,
A LITTLE PIMENTO...
THAT'S A HEART ATTACK
WAITING TO HAPPEN.
VALLEY OF THE DOG.
COME ON OVER HERE.
YOU'RE IN ON THIS.
(grunts)
GOOD.
THAT'S PRETTY
OUT OF BOUNDS, HUH?
THAT'S AWESOME.
WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO DO NEXT?
LET'S CORNDOG-DIP
A TUNA FISH SANDWICH.
OR MAYBE WE'LL MAKE
SOME BURGERS
THAT ARE OUT OF BOUNDS.
(Guy) CAN YOU EAT
THAT WHOLE THING?
WE START WITH JUST BALLS
OF MEAT--
5-OUNCE BALLS OF MEAT.
THEY'RE FLATTENED ON THE FLIP
AND SERVED UP
SMALL BLOCK, BIG BLOCK
OR GET THIS ONE.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS THAT?
FULL-BLOWN HEMI--
THE BEST SANDWICH
IN CHARLOTTE.
FULL-BLOWN HEMI.
YOU'VE HAD THIS BEFORE?
DOZENS OF TIMES.
DUDE! THAT IS
OUT OF BOUNDS.
SO WHAT IS IT?
IT'S THREE PATTIES--
THREE HUGE PATTIES.
AND YOU CAN
REALLY EAT THAT?
IT'LL BE ALL
I EAT TODAY.
WILL YOU BE ABLE
TO FINISH IT, THOUGH?
I THINK I CAN
FINISH THIS.
WE'LL SEE HOW HE DOES
WHEN WE COME BACK.
AT THE PENGUIN IN CHARLOTTE,
YOU JUST GOTTA LOOK
AT THE LINE...
WE HAVE TO TAKE THE PHONE
OFF THE HOOK, 'CAUSE WE CAN'T
DO ANY MORE.
TO KNOW THIS PLACE
IS RIGHT ON POINT...
Y'ALL ENJOY, OKAY?
AND THE BURGERS
ARE A BIG REASON WHY...
THE BEST HAMBURGERS
I'VE EVER TASTED.
STACKED AS BIG
AS A POUND OF BEEF,
TOPPED ANY WAY YOU LIKE IT.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S GOT EVERYTHING
THAT I WANT ON IT.
I LOVE SLAW AND CHILI. IT'S GOT
IT AND THE BURGER'S REALLY GOOD.
ALMOST EVERYTHING'S HUGE HERE.
CHECK OUT THE CHICKEN SANDWICH
AND THE PULLED PORK.
BUT YOU CAN GO
A DIFFERENT WAY.
SO TO MAKE
THE BLACK BEAN HUMMUS--
NOW THIS IS A RECIPE
THAT YOU BROUGHT IN,
OR DID YOU MAKE IT UP HERE?
I MADE IT UP MYSELF.
PUT ONE WHOLE LIME IN.
I GOT A COOL LITTLE ONE
FOR YOU.
WHEN YOU'RE USING--WHEN LIMES
ARE KINDA OUT OF SEASON,
OR LEMONS ARE OUT OF SEASON,
NUKE 'EM FOR ABOUT TEN SECONDS.
YOU'LL REALLY SEE 'EM
OPEN UP. ANY JUICE
THAT'S IN THAT DRIED-UP,
SHRIVELED, IMPORTED THING--
1 TEASPOON OF CINNAMON,
A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN,
1 OF CORIANDER.
SOME SALT AND A BIG SCOOP
OF CHILI POWDER.
THIS IS NO MILD HUMMUS.
IT'LL HAVE A KICK TO IT.
AND THIS IS
THE BLACK BEAN HUMMUS.
I LIKE IT.
LET'S TRY IT.
WOW.
THANKS.
THAT'S GOOD, MAN.
NOW HUMMUS IN A BURGER
AND CORNDOG JOINT
IS JUST PART
OF THE PLANNED CONFUSION
THAT MAKES THE PENGUIN
SO POPULAR.
EVERYBODY LOVES TO COME HERE,
AND BECAUSE IT IS ALTERNATIVE,
THERE'S A GREAT MIX OF PEOPLE.
YOU NEVER KNOW.
SOMEBODY COULD BE
IN A BUSINESS SUIT,
OR THEY COULD BE IN, LIKE,
THEIR RAGGED-OUT CLOTHES
WITH TATTOOS AND--YOU KNOW,
IT'S JUST A GREAT MIX
OF ECLECTIC PEOPLE.
MY NAME'S WILLIAM.
A PLACE THAT CATERS
TO FAMILIES AND KIDS...
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
SINCE THEY WERE REALLY LITTLE.
BUT STILL KINDA LOOKS
LIKE A BIKER BAR.
"KING OF THE NIGHTTIME..."
"KING OF THE NIGHTTIME WORLD."
THAT'S AN OLD KISS SONG
THAT--
I'M MORE KING
OF THE LATE AFTERNOON NOW
AS I GET OLDER.
AS LONG AS HE GETS HIS COOKIN'
DONE BEFORE THEN,
THE FOLKS IN HERE
ARE GONNA DO JUST FINE.
THE PICKLES, THE DOGS--
AND REMEMBER THAT GUY
WITH THE FULL-BLOWN HEMI?
I TOLD YOU WE'D CHECK BACK.
YOU'RE ALMOST DONE
ON THIS THING.
WHOO!
ARE YOU GONNA MAKE IT?
I THINK I'LL MAKE IT.
YOU THINK HE'S GONNA BE ABLE
TO EAT THE WHOLE THING?
OKAY, HERE IT GOES.
HE HAS
A BIG MOUTH...
YEAH, HE GOT IT ALL IN THERE.
I'M IMPRESSED, MAN.
I'M ORDERING YOU
ANOTHER ONE RIGHT NOW.
WANT TO SEE MY...
OH, GOD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROUND
OF TRIPLE Ds.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
WHEN WE'RE OUT LOOKING
FOR CLASSIC RESTAURANTS
AND FUNKY JOINTS
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
HOW'S IT LOOK?
PERFECT.
COMFORTABLE?