HI, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR SOME
OF AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
OKAY, I LIKE THE WAY
THAT'S LOOKIN'.
HOUSE SPECIALS, LIKE
A HAM AND EGG PANCAKE...
THAT'S WEIRD.
AT A SEATTLE JOINT
WHERE THEY'RE SMOKIN' SALMON
IN THE PARKING LOT...
I THINK THIS IS WHAT
EVERYBODY EXPECTS TO SEE
WHEN THEY COME
TO A BREAKFAST JOINT.
EGGS BENEDICT
AFTER BENEDICT
AFTER BENEDICT...
I GET THIS EVERY TIME I COME.
AT A FAMILY-RUN FAVORITE
IN MY HOMETOWN...
HOW ARE
THOSE PANCAKES, BUDDY?
THE BEST THINGS I EVER HAD.
AND THE 85-YEAR-OLD DINER
THAT'S PACKIN' 'EM IN
IN MANCHESTER, NEW HAMPSHIRE...
HOW YA DOIN'?
NO, COME ON IN. I'M IN LINE.
WHERE YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT
THEY'RE BAKING FROM SCRATCH.
IT TASTES BETTER
THAN THE REAL THING.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
NORMALLY WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT ENTERTAINMENT
WHILE YOU'RE EATING,
WELL, YOU'D THINK
YOU'RE AT A VEGAS DINNER SHOW.
BUT LET'S SAY YOU'RE IN SEATTLE
DOWN BY THE WATERFRONT.
YOU'LL FIND AN ENTERTAINING CREW
SERVIN' UP STUFFED GRAPE LEAVES,
SMOKED PORK BENEDICT AND SOME
KILLER HOMEMADE BLUEBERRY PIE
AT A PLACE
CALLED VOULA'S OFFSHORE CAFé.
WELCOME.
WELCOME. WELL...
THANK YOU.
I DON'T GET THAT EVERY TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU DON'T?
NO, I DON'T WALK IN
AND GET HUGGED.
THANK GOODNESS, BECAUSE...
I ALWAYS LIKE
HANDSOME MAN, BABY.
TO VOULA VLAHOS,
EVERY CUSTOMER IS FAMILY.
ALL THIS KIDS
IS MY CUSTOMERS' KIDS.
IF YOU LOVE THE CUSTOMERS,
YOU HAVE TO HUG 'EM.
YOU HAVE TO WELCOME...
WHERE DID YOU GET
THIS PHILOSOPHY
OF RESTAURANT?
GREEK PHILOSOPHY.
THIS IS GREEK PHILOSOPHY?
YES.
AND THAT PHILOSOPHY
INCLUDES TONS OF HOMEMADE FOOD,
FROM EGG SCRAMBLES
FILLED WITH MEAT AND CHEESE...
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST GOOD,
HEARTY, FEEL-GOOD FOOD.
TO HOMEMADE BLUEBERRY PIE.
I'VE HAD ALMOST EVERYTHING HERE,
AND EVERYTHING'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S JUST A GREAT RESTAURANT
RUN BY A GREAT FAMILY.
ON THE LINE, YOU'LL FIND
VOULA'S TWO SONS--
NIKOS...
CHOP.
(Guy) FLIP.
YOU'RE THE POTATO MASTER.
YEAH.
AND SIKEY.
IS IT 'CAUSE HE'S
THE OLDER BROTHER
HE GETS
TO WORK THE BELL?
UH, NO. HE'S IN--
THAT'S HIS SECTION...
LOOK AT HIM.
TOAST AND CASH REGISTER.
WHAT'S THIS ONE
WITH POTATO SALAD DOWN HERE?
AND AFTER WORKING
ALONGSIDE THESE GUYS
FOR THE PAST 15 YEARS, BRYAN
IS PRACTICALLY FAMILY, TOO.
PUT IT ON THERE,
TURN AROUND, GRAB SOME BUTTER.
YOU'RE GONNA DO
A PIROUETTE?
YEAH, AND THEN WATCH,
THAT IS HIS JOB RIGHT THERE.
YOU SEE HIM WORKIN'?
SEE ME WORK?
SKILL.
YEAH. THANK YOU.
THE SKILL--CAN WE
GET THAT IN SLO-MO?
(imitating slo-mo)
OKAY.
ORDER UP.
(laughs)
AND MOM WORKS IT
AS THE FOREMAN.
SHE LOOKS LIKE...
OH, LOOK, LOOK.
YES.
OH, NOW WE HAVE
A DANCE COMING OUT.
THAT'S HOW WE ROLL.
"THAT'S HOW WE ROLL."
AND THEY'VE BEEN ROLLIN'
LIKE THAT SINCE 1984
WHEN VOULA BOUGHT THE PLACE TO
HELP PUT SIKEY THROUGH COLLEGE.
SHE PAID FOR YOU TO GO
TO SCHOOL, AND YOU CAME BACK.
I NEVER LEFT.
AND I'D GO TO SCHOOL
AFTER WORK.
AND THEN COME BACK HERE?
AND MASTER THE MENU
THAT VOULA PUT TOGETHER.
IT JUST HAS
THAT PERFECT BUTTERY--
THAT WE ONLY ALLOW
OURSELVES ONCE A WEEK,
BECAUSE IT IS
SO DELICIOUS.
THE INDULGENCE.
WHAT'S THAT?
GREEK HOBO.
NO, THIS,
NOT YOUR BROTHER.
(Sikey) OHH! YOU'RE A COMEDIAN.
YOU'RE GOOD.
GREEK HOBO--WE PUT
ONIONS, MUSHROOMS...
I ALREADY LIKE THE WAY
THAT STARTS OUT.
GREEK SAUSAGE.
AND WHAT IS GREEK SAUSAGE?
BEEF--SPICED BEEF.
SPICED BEEF--
IS IT LIKE GYRO MEAT?
THIS IS--WE USE IT
FOR THE GYRO, TOO.
HASH BROWNS.
HOW MANY EGGS
DOES IT GET?
TWO.
MIX IT TOGETHER.
MIX.
AND YOU DON'T HAVE
ALL THIS PREMADE.
IT'S NOT LIKE PEOPLE
COME IN HERE AND THINK...
NO.
EVERYTHING WE DO
IS PRETTY MUCH MADE TO ORDER.
FETA GOES ON HERE NOW,
NOT ON THE PLATE?
FETA ON TOP.
FRESH GRATED FETA.
OHH, YOU DON'T SEE
THAT EVERY DAY.
GIVE ME SOME OF THAT
IN MY HAND. OHH, THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S A PARTY.
WOW, THAT IS GOOD.
THAT'S IT, BUDDY,
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THAT MIGHT BE ONE OF
THE BEST BREAKFAST SCRAMBLES
I'VE--YOU KNOW, OR ONE
OF THE MOST UNIQUE
BREAKFAST SCRAMBLES
I'VE EVER HEARD OF.
I GIVE YOU ALL KINDS
OF PROPS ON THAT.
CAN YOU EAT
THE WHOLE THING?
I BRING THREE PEOPLE.
YOU NEED THREE PEOPLE
TO EAT THE HOBO?
I LOVE THE HOBO.
BUT IT ISN'T JUST THE HOBO.
IT'S EVERYTHING
VOULA'S GOT ON THE MENU...
OH, HI, GUYS.
FROM BASIC...
THE BEST MEAT LOAF
I'VE EVER HAD.
TO BIZARRE.
I RECOMMEND
THE CHINESE PANCAKE.
(Guy) YOU HAVE GOT
TO BE KIDDING ME.
NO, THIS IS FOR REAL.
SO WHAT MAKES IT CHINESE?
I DON'T KNOW.
PEOPLE ORDER HAM,
EGGS AND PANCAKE.
RIGHT.
WHY DON'T WE JUST
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER?
DOES IT GET FLIPPED?
HOPEFULLY. (laughs)
ROUND OF APPLAUSE,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THANK YOU.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THAT DOES WORK, MAN.
IT DOES WORK.
HANDS DOWN,
TO THIS DAY--
THE WEIRDEST THING
I'VE EVER SEEN...
IT IS.
FOR BREAKFAST.
THAT'S WEIRD.
BUT NOT AS WEIRD AS WHAT'S
GOIN' ON IN THE PARKING LOT...
I THINK THIS IS WHAT
EVERYBODY EXPECTS TO SEE
WHEN THEY COME
TO A BREAKFAST JOINT.
WHERE BRYAN'S SMOKING
FRESH PACIFIC SALMON...
WOW, THAT'S
LOOKIN' GREAT.
FOR THEIR SMOKY
THE SALMON SCRAMBLE.
(Nikos) ARE YOU READY FOR THIS?
WE'RE GONNA PLATE IT UP.
AH, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THERE YOU GO.
WOW. NICE AND LIGHT.
IS THAT A BIG SELLER?
OH, HUGE.
THIS IS THE BEST THING
I'VE EVER HAD HERE, ACTUALLY.
AND VOULA'S OFF-THE-HOOK MENU
GOES ON AND ON.
I'M GONNA PUT IT
FAT SIDE DOWN.
BACK TO PARKING LOT
FOR SMOKED PORK BUTT
FOR A PORK AND CHIPOTLE
EGGS BENEDICT.
THAT'S MY MOM'S RECIPE.
VOULA'S DOING
TRADITIONAL GREEK FAVORITES
LIKE HAND-ROLLED BEEF-
AND-RICE-FILLED GRAPE LEAVES.
OHH! HOW DO YOU
SAY 'EM IN GREEK?
DOLMADES.
DOLMADES?
YES.
DOLMADES.
(speaking Greek)
OH, EXACTLY.
MMM.
I WOULDN'T...
I WOULDN'T
DRIVE BY HERE
AND THINK I'M GONNA...
COME IN HERE
AND GET THIS.
SHE'S EVEN MAKING
HOMEMADE BLUEBERRY PIE
FROM ACTUAL BERRIES
THAT HAVEN'T EVEN BEEN
IN THE FREEZER.
I LIKE HOW THE BERRIES
AREN'T GUMMED UP
WITH A BUNCH OF FILLER.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
BUT EVEN MORE THAN HER FOOD...
IT WAS NICE
TO SEE YOU GUYS.
IT'S VOULA HERSELF
WHO'S BEEN COLLECTING
SO MANY REGULARS
OVER THE YEARS.
I'LL SEE YOU
NEXT THURSDAY? BYE-BYE.
YEAH.
THE BOYS ARE DOING ALL THEY CAN
TO KEEP EVERYTHING
THE WAY MOM STARTED IT.
PEOPLE ARE TRYIN'
TO WORK AROUND HERE.
WELL, WHERE ARE THEY?
(laughs mockingly)
AND TECHNICALLY,
VOULA ISN'T EVEN HERE ANYMORE.
SHE'LL TELL YOU
SHE RETIRED SIX MONTHS AGO,
BUT SHE JUST CAN'T STAY AWAY.
AH, COME ON.
AFTER ALL, THE NAME
OF THE JOINT IS VOULA'S.
WE COME IN HERE,
AND WE SING--
♪ VOULA, VOULA
VOULA, VOULA ♪
YOU CAN'T RETIRE.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS DOESN'T LOOK RETIRED.
BABY, THANK YOU.
KEEP GOING. KEEP GOING.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING TO ONE
OF MY HOMETOWN FAVORITES...
HASH BROWNS?
WHERE MAKING PANCAKES
FROM SCRATCH MEANS
REALLY FROM SCRATCH.
WE GRIND THE WHOLE WHEAT.
WOW!
WE'RE TRAVELING THROUGH
SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA--
MY HOMETOWN--IN THE HEART
OF THE WINE COUNTRY.
IT'S ABOUT REAL PEOPLE
SERVING UP REAL FOOD
LIKE AT HANK'S CREEKSIDE.
ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT I LOVE ABOUT THE PLACE
IS HANK HIMSELF--A FATHER OF SIX
WHO COOKS THE SHOW IN
THE CENTER OF THE DINING ROOM.
ORDER UP, LINDA.
NORMALLY, HANK,
WHEN WE SHOOT THE SHOW,
THE PERSON I'M INTERVIEWING
OR TALKING TO
DOESN'T DWARF ME COMPLETELY.
GIVE ME A WINGSPAN.
NOW GO LIKE THIS--
(squawks)
THIS BIG GUY'S BEEN
CRANKING OUT BIG FOOD HERE
FOR 15 YEARS.
IT WAS A GREAT MEAL.
NEVER HAD A BAD ONE HERE.
HOW ARE
THOSE PANCAKES, BUDDY?
THE CHOCOLATE CHIP PANCAKES
ARE THE BEST THINGS I EVER HAD.
FROM THE BREAKFAST BASICS
TO BENEDICTS...
I GOT EGGS BENEDICT.
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
TO BLINTZES...
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL DONE TO ORDER FOR A CROWD
THAT KEEPS COMIN' BACK.
IT'S LIKE
HOME-COOKED FOOD.
A VERY LOCAL
HAPPENING PLACE.
CAN I GET A LOAF
OF WHOLE WHEAT?
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LOOK
FOR OTHER PLACES
WHEN YOU HAVE HANK'S.
EGGS BENEDICT,
HASH BROWNS.
THANK YOU.
LET'S JUST LET
THE CAT OUT OF THE BAG--
ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES
TO COME, AND I CAN'T
EVEN GET A RESERVATION,
'CAUSE THEY DON'T TAKE
ANY RESERVATIONS
AT HANK'S CREEKSIDE.
HOW LONG WILL THE WAIT GET
ON ONE OF THE LONGEST DAYS,
LIKE ON SUNDAYS?
IT COULD BE
30 MINUTES ON SUNDAY.
I'VE BEEN HERE ON
A 45-MINUTE DAY SUNDAY, SO...
WELL, FOR EVERYBODY ELSE,
IT'S 30.
AND I'LL STAND IN LINE
FOR HANK'S HOMEMADE HASH.
WHEN I COME HERE,
I ORDER THE HASH
AS AN APPETIZER
TO MY BREAKFAST.
I WAS HOPIN' THEY'D
GIVE ME THE RECIPE,
BECAUSE IT'S SO--
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
OKAY, SLICE UP
A CORNED BEEF BRISKET.
FEED ONE IN.
I GOT IT. I GOT IT.
IT'S GOT TO DEFINITELY
MAKE A TEXTURE DIFFERENCE
VERSUS JUST CHOPPING IT
AND CUBING IT.
I THINK IT MIXES
INSIDE THE POTATOES
A LITTLE BIT NICER.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
THAT'S ALL THE POTATOES
THAT GO IN THERE?
THAT'S IT.
WHAT'S THE RATIO
OF POTATO TO MEAT?
OH, 8 TO 2.
5 TO 1.
20 TO 4.
I DON'T KNOW.
WE CALL THE POTATO
"HASH HELPER."
POTATO HASH HELPER...
YEAH.
NOT JUST FOR BREAKFAST
ANYMORE.
(Guy) HOLY HASH, BATMAN.
LISTEN, YOU'RE SAYIN'
I GET A BIG ORDER.
YOU DON'T EVER GET
MY ORDER THAT BIG.
IT'LL COOK DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
OH, OKAY.
I LIKE THE WAY
THAT'S LOOKIN'.
MMM. I GOTTA TELL YA,
THE CRUNCH--
THERE'S A TON
OF CORNED BEEF IN IT.
THERE'S
NOT JUST POTATOES.
IT'S BASIC.
IT'S SIMPLE...
RIGHT.
BUT IT'S MONEY.
OF COURSE, NOT EVERYTHING'S
SIMPLE HERE.
EGGS BENEDICT?
ONE EGGS BENEDICT?
MY EGGS BENEDICT'S
THE BEST.
YOU GOT TO MAKE A CHOICE--
TRADITIONAL,
FLORENTINE WITH FRESH SPINACH,
THE BENEDICT ARNOLD
WITH SMOKED SALMON...
I GET THIS EVERY TIME I COME.
I WOULDN'T MISS IT.
HOMEMADE CRAB CAKE BENEDICT
OR CALIFORNIA STYLE.
(Hank) AVOCADO, TOMATO,
POACHED EGG, HOLLANDAISE,
ENGLISH MUFFIN.
THAT CALIFORNIA BENEDICT
IS MONEY.
WHO CAME UP
WITH ALL THE MENU ITEMS?
WELL, I DID.
YOU SEE HANK'S
REALLY IS HANK'S.
YOU COME THROUGH THE DOOR.
HE'S THERE--6'6".
"HI, HOW ARE YOU?"
WAVIN' TO YOU.
AND IT'S RUN BY FAMILY, SO YOU
GET THE FEELING OF FAMILY...
HE'S GOT ENOUGH KIDS
THAT HE COULD ALMOST HAVE
A BASEBALL TEAM.
YES, THEY COULD.
THIS IS ALMOST
A BASEBALL TEAM.
NOW HOW MANY OF YOUR KIDS--
YOU HAVE SIX KIDS...
RIGHT.
NOW HAS EVERYBODY AT SOME POINT
IN TIME WORKED HERE?
OH, YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
TODAY IT'S HANK'S WIFE LINDA
AND A HANDFUL OF THE KIDS.
HE'S NOT EASY TO LIVE WITH,
BUT HE'S A GOOD MAN.
SAME HUMOR FROM THE REST
OF THE STAFF.
TOUGH JOB?
YEAH, IT'S HOT...
HOT.
LOW PAY.
AND HARD WORK,
EVEN SOMETHING
AS SIMPLE AS PANCAKES--
OUT-OF-BOUNDS HOMEMADE.
WE GRIND THE WHOLE WHEAT.
WOW! YOU REALLY--
I MEAN,
THAT'S NO JOKE.
I LIKE IT A LITTLE FINER.
I PUT IT
ABOUT RIGHT THERE,
AND IT'S PULVERIZING IT.
IS IT DOING IT
RIGHT NOW?
IT IS.
YOU'LL SEE IT DROP DOWN.
IT'S A SLOW PROCESS.
AND WHY GRIND
YOUR OWN WHOLE WHEAT?
CAN'T YOU FIND
WHOLE WHEAT THAT'S GROUND?
IT LOSES A LOT
OF NUTRITIONAL VALUE
IF YOU GET IT
ALREADY GROUND.
SO HOW MANY PANCAKES
WILL THIS MAKE?
I WOULD GUESS 30, 40.
30, 40?
I'M GUESSIN'.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA COUNT?
I NEVER HAVE--
1, 2, 3, 7, 11, 40.
THAT'S A THICK PANCAKE.
YEAH, IT'S A NICE...
AND THAT'S
GOTTA BE DENSE.
IT'S PRETTY HEAVY-DUTY.
BLUEBERRIES, STRAWBERRIES?
BLUEBERRIES, BANANAS,
STRAWBERRIES.
OKAY, SO JUST THROW
SOME BLUEBERRIES IN ON TOP?
OR PLACE, YEAH.
JUST KINDA SPRINKLE 'EM.
OKAY, SO ARE THESE
READY TO GO?
I THINK SO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
AARON? PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
I STILL GOT IT, BABY.
THAT'S ONE NICE--
HE'S STILL GOT IT
IN HIS WRIST?
YEP.
NICE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THAT
WHEN I CRACKED INTO--
THAT'S A GOOD PANCAKE, HANK.
I LIKE IT. MAY I?
IT TASTES LIKE DESSERT.
BUT IF THAT'S DESSERT,
WHAT'S THE CINNAMON WALNUT
FRENCH TOAST?
LOOK AT THIS BREAD.
OH, IT'S
BEAUTIFUL BREAD.
THAT IS
DENSE AND RICH.
RIGHT.
I'M JUST GONNA PUT
A LITTLE EGG WASH IN IT.
AND JUST FLIP IT?
BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE
DONE IT BEFORE.
I'VE DONE IT BEFORE.
WHAT GOES ON THIS?
A LITTLE POWDERED SUGAR.
THAT IS DESSERT.
IT NEEDS A SCOOP
OF ICE CREAM ON IT.
WOW. I WOULD BE SCRAPING
HUNTER OFF THE CEILING
IF HE ATE THAT.
AND THERE'S
THE ESSENCE OF HANK'S.
FROM FRENCH TOAST
TO FRESH BENEDICT,
IT'S A LITTLE SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE--
ALL OF IT MADE FRESH,
ALL OF IT MADE WELL,
SERVED BY A FAMILY AT A PLACE
THAT FEELS LIKE HOME.
I'M REALLY BACK HERE.
TRUST ME.
WHENEVER YOU DON'T SEE ME,
I'M JUST GONNA HAVE--
YOU KNOW, LIKE SOMETHING
OUT ON THE SAND DUNES.
I SHOULD HAVE LIKE
A LITTLE ORANGE FLAG--
SO WHERE'S GUIDO?
BEHIND THE HANK.
HI.
HI. WELCOME BACK.
WELL, IT'S GREAT
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
NEXT WE'RE HEADING
TO AN 85-YEAR-OLD
NEW HAMPSHIRE CLASSIC
TO LEARN THE SECRETS
OF A NEW ENGLAND FAVORITE.
YOU NEVER HEARD
OF AMERICAN CHOP SUEY?
NO.
REALLY?
I'M HERE
AT MANCHESTER, NEW HAMPSHIRE.
PEOPLE AROUND THESE PARTS
KNOW THAT THE RED ARROW
IS THE 24-7 GO-TO SPOT
FOR GREAT DINER FOOD
THAT'S TOTALLY WORTH THE WAIT.
DOES EVERYBODY JUST
STAND IN LINE LIKE THIS?
THEY DO.
EVERYBODY STANDS...
HOW YA DOIN'?
NO, COME ON IN. I'M IN LINE.
IN LINE--YOU WANT CUTS?
MORNING.
HI.
AND THEY ALL KNOW
WHAT ORDER THEY'RE IN,
'CAUSE THEY'LL,
YOU KNOW...
THEY'LL SELF-GOVERN.
THEY'LL PIPE UP.
AND IT'S BEEN THAT WAY
SINCE 1922
AT THIS NEW HAMPSHIRE LEGEND
WHERE THEY BRAG
THEY'RE ONLY CLOSED
16 HOURS A YEAR.
WE CLOSE CHRISTMAS EVE
AT 2:00 P.M.,
AND WE REOPEN CHRISTMAS DAY
AT 6:00 A.M.--
BUSIEST DAY OF THE YEAR.
CAROL SHEEHAN GREW UP
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ,
AND FOR THE LAST 20 YEARS,
SHE'S BEEN KEEPING
THIS PLACE CLASSIC.
HOW MANY YEARS
YOU BEEN COMIN' HERE?
ALMOST TEN.
REALLY?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
AWESOME.
WELL, I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
(Guy) REALLY?
YEAH, I'D SAY 12 YEARS.
I'VE ALWAYS LIKED THIS PLACE
BECAUSE OF THE ATMOSPHERE.
IT'S LIKE BEING HOME.
WITH REAL HOME COOKIN' HEAVY
ON THE NEW ENGLAND TRADITIONS
LIKE CORNED BEEF
AND CABBAGE...
THE BEST IN TOWN.
HOMEMADE BAKED BEANS WITH TOAST
OR JUST PLAIN
OLD COMFORT FOOD...
(Guy) EXTRA GRAVY?
THAT'S EXTRA GRAVY.
LIKE FRESH ROAST TURKEY,
EVEN THEIR OWN VERSION
OF A BRITISH SHEPHERD'S PIE.
IN THE WINDOW!
AND EACH DAY OF THE WEEK,
THERE'S A DIFFERENT
BLUE PLATE SPECIAL.
I THINK
WE'RE PRETTY UNIQUE,
BECAUSE WE DO ACTUALLY
SERVE IT ON A BLUE PLATE.
SWEET!
AND FOR THE PAST FIVE YEARS,
THE GUY BEHIND THE BLUE PLATE
HAS BEEN ROY DONOHUE.
ROY, YOU'RE
THE CHEF DE CUISINE HERE.
I AM THE CHEF DE CUISINE.
"I AM THE CHEF DE CUISINE."
I'VE BEEN IN KITCHENS
PRETTY MUCH MOST OF MY LIFE.
YOU'RE A FOOD DUDE,
AREN'T YOU?
I'M A FOOD DUDE.
WHAT IS ROY'S
HANDS-DOWN SPECIALTY?
EVERY SINGLE HOMEMADE FOOD THERE
IS IN AMERICA, I LOVE TO MAKE.
YOU LOVE TO MAKE?
I LOVE TO MAKE.
EVERY WEDNESDAY, THE BLUE PLATE
SPECIAL IS AMERICAN CHOP SUEY.
A WHAT? WHAT?
YOU NEVER HEARD
OF AMERICAN CHOP SUEY?
NO.
REALLY?
YOU DON'T KNOW
ABOUT AMERICAN CHOP SUEY?
BRO, I DON'T THINK
ANYBODY ELSE DOES.
YOU ALL KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
RIGHT, YOU GUYS
ALL KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
YOU KNOW WHAT
AMERICAN CHOP SUEY IS?
OF COURSE I DO.
"OF COURSE I DO."
IT'S JUST--
ALL-AMERICAN HAMBURG
AND MACARONI.
IT'S AMERICAN CHOP...
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHERE CHOP SUEY CAME FROM!
WELL, I DON'T KNOW, BUT IT'S
YEARS AND YEARS AND YEARS
I'VE HEARD OF CHOP SUEY
UP HERE IN NEW ENGLAND.
IT'S GOT TO BE
A THING IN NEW ENGLAND.
OKAY, GIVE IT TO ME.
HOW DO WE MAKE IT?
OKAY, WHAT WE DO IS
WE TAKE A HEATED PAN HERE
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER IN THERE--BUTTER.
BUTTER?
BUTTER.
NOT OIL.
NOT OIL, BUTTER.
DROP THAT BABY RIGHT IN THERE.
WOW.
SQUEEZE THAT 5 POUND
RIGHT IN THERE.
WELCOME
TO ROY'S COOKING SHOW.
ROY'S COOKING SHOW.
WE THROW IN
A COUPLE ONIONS HERE.
I MEAN,
I ALWAYS DUMP 'EM IN.
YEAH? SHOW ME.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
THAT'S ENOUGH RIGHT THERE.
SAUTé A LITTLE BIT THERE.
OKAY, SO A COUPLE CUPS OF--
IT HAS TO BE GREEN BELL PEPPER?
GREEN BELL PEPPER.
GREEN BELL PEPPER--HAS
TO BE GREEN BELL PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA WANT
SOME BLACK PEPPER IN THERE.
GARLIC, OREGANO, BASIL?
GARLIC, OREGANO, BASIL.
SO STIR THAT IN,
AND ANOTHER CAN OF TOMATO SAUCE?
NO, THIS IS TOMATO STRIPS.
TOMATO STRIPS?
THESE ARE
80-40 TOMATO STRIPS.
THEY ARE--WHOA.
JEEZ, ROY!
I GUESS THAT'S WHY YOU
SHOULD WEAR AN APRON.
OH, IS THAT
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL MEAL?
SWEET!
MIX IT UP?
MIX IT UP.
IN THE WORLD OF NEW ENGLAND
AND CHOP SUEY,
IS THIS RIGHT UP THERE
PRETTY HIGH?
THIS IS ONE HEARTY MEAL.
MAKE SURE YOU GET
THEM TOMATO STRIPS IN THERE.
GET THEM STRIPS.
NOW YOU THROW
A LITTLE PARMESAN ON THERE.
I COULD PUT ABOUT 7
OR 15,000 POUNDS ON THIS.
ABSOLUTELY.
WOW. I NEVER TRIED
THE CHOP SUEY.
I'D TRY THAT.
YOU THINK SO?
I'VE TRIED THE CHOP SUEY.
OH, YOU HAVE?
I MADE IT.
OH, YOU MADE IT?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M REALLY OVER HERE--
IS I'M JUST KINDA WORKIN'
MY ANGLE FOR A LITTLE
"THAT'S THE BEST CHOP SUEY
I EVER HAD." AH, THANK YOU.
AND IT ISN'T JUST
THE CHOP SUEY.
THE RED ARROW MENU'S
FULL OF STUFF THAT FOLKS
AROUND HERE GREW UP WITH.
THE BEAN RECIPE'S FROM 1922.
YOU'VE GOT BROWN SUGAR.
YOU GOT MOLASSES.
(both) SWEET!
AND ROY'S GOT HIS OWN SPIN
ON EVERYTHING,
LIKE FRENCH TOAST.
HE DEEP-FRIES IT.
NEVER SEEN IT IN MY LIFE.
LOOK AT THE THINGS
YOU'RE LEARNING HERE.
LIKE CLOSE ENCOUNTERS
OF THE ROY KIND.
ROY KIND.
AND THEN THERE'S SOMETHING
CALLED A PORK PIE.
THAT'S ANOTHER BLUE PLATE
SPECIAL--PORK PIE.
IT'S MY GRANDMOTHER'S
RECIPE.
DONE ROY STYLE
WITH GROUND PORK, SPICES
AND A KIND
OF A POULTRY SEASONING.
THIS IS WHAT MAKES
OUR PORK PIE OUR PORK PIE...
THIS IS THE KEY...
THE RED ARROW PORK PIE.
THIS IS IT?
IT'S IT.
AND IT'S ALL WHIPPED UP WITH
SOME HOMEMADE MASHED POTATOES.
SO IT'S NOT A LAYER OF PORK
AND A LAYER OF POTATOES.
NO, IT'S NOT.
IT'S ALL MIXED
RIGHT TOGETHER.
YOU EVER GET
YOUR MUSTACHE STUCK IN IT?
UH, NO, BUT I DO GET
POTATOES STUCK
ON MY MUSTACHE
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE.
SAFETY SHIELD--
SAFETY FIRST.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S IT.
COULD YOU GET
A SMALLER ROLLING PIN?
NO, THAT'S THE SIZE
THAT I LIKE TO USE.
A BIG GUY, YOU KNOW--
PERFECT.
THAT'S ABOUT AS MUCH BAKING
AS I KNOW HOW TO DO.
WELL, YOU DID
A FINE JOB THERE.
AND NOW WE COVER IT.
ARE YOU THIS MUCH
OF A PERFECTIONIST
ABOUT ALL THE FOOD
YOU COOK?
I TRY TO BE.
I MEAN, YOU JUST TOOK
AS MUCH TIME AS I WOULD SEE
A GRANDMOTHER TAKING
ON A PIE THAT SHE WAS BAKING
FOR HER GRANDCHILDREN.
WELL, I TAKE PRIDE IN IT.
THAT'S ALL.
(whistles)
BEAUTIFUL.
I LIKE IT. THAT'S
COMFORT FOOD RIGHT THERE, MAN.
IT'S MOIST. IT'S FLAVORFUL.
YOU GET THE FORK.
YOU GET THE MASHED POTATOES.
IT'S HUGE. IT'S FILLING.
GOOD STUFF, BROTHER.
I'M IMPRESSED.
YEAH.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WAIT TILL YOU SEE
WHAT THEY'RE DOIN'
FOR DESSERT HERE.
I'M LEARNING
THEIR OWN HOMEMADE TAKE...
OH! YEAH.
ON THE ALL-AMERICAN TWINKIE.
I HAD A TWINKIE BLOWOUT.
AT THE RED ARROW DINER
IN MANCHESTER, NEW HAMPSHIRE,
IT'S 24-7
FOR ANY MEAL YOU WANT...
I ALWAYS GET
BREAKFAST--PANCAKES,
SAUSAGE, EGGS BENEDICT.
IT'S HOMEMADE. IT'S FRESH.
NOTHING IS PROCESSED.
AND ROY'S MAKIN' SURE OF IT.
DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER
THAN THIS, PEOPLE.
BUT WHEN IT'S TIME
FOR DESSERT...
THE PIE.
I COULD NEVER BAKE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS,
SO I COME HERE INSTEAD.
THAT'S WHEN RACHEL STEPS IN.
NOW HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN BAKING?
ALL MY LIFE.
SHE DOES IT ALL--PIES, CAKES,
BUT HER TRUE CLAIM TO FAME
MIGHT JUST BE
THIS LITTLE MASTERPIECE.
LOOK FAMILIAR? AROUND HERE,
THEY CALL IT THE DINAH FINGER.
YOU'RE GONNA PROBABLY WIN,
LIKE, AN AWARD HERE
IN THE COMMUNITY
FOR MAKING REAL TWINKIES
OR REAL DINAH FINGERS.
WHAT INSPIRES YOU?
I WANTED SNACK CAKES
THAT WE ENJOYED AS KIDS
BUT BETTER.
IT'S VERY GOOD. IT TASTES
BETTER THAN THE REAL THING.
(Guy) REGULAR OLD
POUND CAKE MIX?
IT IS. IT IS.
I USE ANYWHERE FROM
3/4 CUP TO A CUP OF WATER.
NOW IS THAT WHAT YOU WOULD
READ IF YOU READ A BOOK--
OR IF YOU READ THE BOX...
NO.
IF YOU KNOW HOW TO READ?
IF I KNOW HOW TO--
SO THIS IS
A DIFFERENT MIXTURE RATIO?
YES.
OKAY.
A LITTLE YELLOW FOOD COLORING
AND SOME EGG WHITES
GIVE 'EM THAT AUTHENTIC
LOOK AND TEXTURE.
SO HOW MANY DIFFERENT BATCHES
OR VARIATIONS DID YOU MAKE
BEFORE YOU GOT THE ONE
YOU WERE HAPPY WITH?
WELL, THEY ATE A LOT
OF TWINKIES BACK HERE.
TAPPY, TAP, TAP.
YES.
AFTER 25 MINUTES IN THE OVEN,
THEY'RE READY FOR A FILLING
THAT INCLUDES
MARSHMALLOW FLUFF,
VANILLA AND POWDERED SUGAR.
AND WE'RE GONNA FILL IT
THE TRADITIONAL WAY,
SO THREE HOLES.
SO YOU JUST PUSH
RIGHT INTO THE DINAH FINGER
AND SQUEEZE,
AND THERE YOU GO.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
CHECK THAT OUT.
THERE YOU GO.
WOW, THAT IS SWEET,
BUT THAT IS GOOD.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
THIS TASTES LIKE
REAL MADE FOOD.
YES.
CAN I FILL ONE?
ABSOLUTELY.
OH! YEAH.
I HAD A TWINKIE BLOWOUT.
BUT RACHEL'S GOT IT COVERED,
JUST LIKE ROY'S ON TOP
OF EVERYTHING ELSE...
BEAUTIFUL.
TO KEEP THIS PLACE AS GOOD
AS IT'S BEEN FOR 85 YEARS NOW--
A LOCAL LANDMARK TOURISTS
ARE TOLD NOT TO MISS...
TRADITIONAL
AMERICAN FOOD, RIGHT?
IN A PLACE WHERE THE LOCALS
ARE STILL LINING UP.
HERE WE COME.
THERE WE GO.
I EAT HERE AT LEAST
FIVE NIGHTS A WEEK.
I'M IN THE GOOD-BYE-
HELLO-WAIT AREA.
GOOD-BYE. HELLO.
THANK YOU. SEE YOU LATER.
BYE! IT'S EXCELLENT.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
WE GOT TO HIT.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THEY'RE BROKEN.
PROVE IT.
I CAN'T.
(laughs)
I MEAN, WE DON'T HAVE
AN UNDER-GRIDDLE CAM.
WE NEED TO GET
UNDER-GRIDDLE CAM.
(radio static)