HI, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
HEADED FOR SOME
OF AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
IT'S TOTALLY BURGERS
DONE EVERY WHICH WAY...
(Guy) OHH!
BURIED IN CHEESE
AND STEAMED WITH ICE
AT A TINY JOINT
IN SACRAMENTO...
(Guy) THE SQUEEZE
WITH CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT.
STUFFED WITH CHEDDAR AND BACON
OR HEAPING WITH BLUE CHEESE...
THAT IS RICH.
AT A CHICAGO AREA LANDMARK
WITH A HISTORY THAT STRETCHES
BACK TO PROHIBITION...
YOU COME AND DRINK THE BEER,
AND THEN WE'LL GIVE YOU
THE BURGER FOR FREE.
AND SIRLOIN GROUND FRESH...
WE DON'T CALL 'EM HAMBURGERS.
THEY'RE STEAK BURGERS.
AT AN INDIANA JOINT WHERE
YOU CAN GET 'EM WITH ANYTHING,
EVEN PEANUT BUTTER.
I ENVY YOU
FOR THE FIRST BITE.
THEN GO AHEAD.
NO. HA HA!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES!"
♪♪
THERE'S A LOT OF GREAT FOOD
HERE IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA,
BETWEEN THE SIERRAS
AND SAN FRANCISCO,
BUT PROBABLY A PLACE
YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT TO FIND
WOULD BE A BURGER JOINT
WHERE THEY PUT
AS MUCH CHEESE ON THEIR BURGER
AS THEY DO MEAT.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
(Guy) OHH!
A 1/3 POUND OF BURGER
AND A 1/3 POUND OF CHEESE.
IT'S CALLED A 5-NAPKIN BURGER--
MESSY, JUICY AND TASTY.
IT'S THE SQUEEZE WITH CHEESE--
AN OFF-THE-HOOK BURGER
COVERED IN CHEDDAR.
THE BEST BURGERS
IN SACRAMENTO.
THAT IS THE CRAZIEST THING
I'VE EVER SEEN.
(woman) WELL, YOU SEE THE CHEESE
JUST HANGS OUT HERE.
IT'S VERY CRISP AND JUST CHEESY.
IT KINDA WAKES UP THE TASTE BUDS
BEFORE YOU BITE
IN THE BIG JUICY BURGER.
WHAT TIME DO YOU OPEN?
(man) 10:00.
AND THEY'RE
ALREADY LININ' UP...
I DRIVE ACROSS TOWN
FOR THIS.
AT THIS TINY 12-STOOL DIVE
CALLED THE SQUEEZE INN.
IT'S HARD TO FIND
A SEAT IN THIS PLACE,
SO WHEN YOU FIND ONE, YOU GOT
TO SIT DOWN AND ENJOY IT.
I THINK THAT'S WHY THEY
MUST CALL IT THE SQUEEZE INN.
YOU'RE ALL SET.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
OWNER TRAVIS HAUSAUER BOUGHT
THIS PLACE SIX YEARS AGO,
AND HE'S KEEPING
A 30-YEAR TRADITION
ALIVE AND KICKIN'.
THAT ONE GOT
A LITTLE BIG ON ME THERE,
BUT WE'RE GONNA, YOU KNOW--
IT'S JUST GONNA GO RIGHT...
HO!
RIGHT THERE.
WE'LL FOLD IT UP.
THAT IS A GOOD-LOOKIN' BURGER.
SEE, I LIKE FLATTOP BURGERS.
YEAH.
I ENJOY 'EM, 'CAUSE YOU
GET THAT LITTLE--
YOU GET THAT LITTLE
CARAMELIZED CRISP THERE.
IT'S ALMOST, UH--
IT'S ALL GOOD FLAVOR.
IT'S THE FAT--OH, YEAH.
OH, THERE'S A LITTLE CRUNCH.
WE'RE GONNA THROW SOME CHEESE
ON IT HERE. JUST GRAB A HANDFUL.
IT COMES OUT--I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S ABOUT 1/4 POUND OR WHAT...
OH, JEEZ!
BUT WE LAY THAT ON THERE.
DID THEY--DID THEY
ASK FOR EXTRA?
NO, THAT'S NORMAL.
THAT'S AS MUCH CHEESE
AS IT IS BURGER.
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
THEN COMES THE TOTALLY
OUT-OF-BOUNDS WAY
THEY FINISH 'EM OFF--
A HANDFUL OF ICE.
ALL THAT'S GONNA DO
IS GENERATE STEAM.
I'M GONNA TAKE THE BUN
LIKE THIS
AND THROW IT ON TOP.
I'M GONNA THROW
A LITTLE MORE ICE ON THERE.
AND THEN YOU'RE
GONNA PUT THE HOOD ON.
THAT DOES NOT MAKE--
I MEAN, IT MAKES SENSE.
WHO INVENTED THIS?
I THINK THE PREVIOUS OWNER
GOT IT GOIN'.
PRETTY UNIQUE
AND ORIGINAL...
PRETTY UNIQUE?
AND PEOPLE LOVE IT.
THIS IS WHAT'S
SO COOL ABOUT IT--
IT COOKS THE CHEESE.
YOU ADD THE STEAM FACTOR--
STEAMS THE BUN,
KEEPS THE BURGER JUICY.
THERE'S COMPONENTS
OF COOKIN' GOIN' ON HERE
THAT I DON'T THINK ANYBODY
WOULD'VE DESIGNED AND SAID,
"THIS IS HOW THIS IS GONNA
WORK," BUT THIS REALLY WORKS.
IT DOES.
I MEAN,
THIS REALLY WORKS.
(Travis) I'M PULLIN'
THE HOOD OFF.
WOW!
SO THAT'S IT
RIGHT THERE.
SEE HOW THAT CHEESE JUST
ALL MELTED DOWN ON THERE?
NOW THAT BUN...
NOW DOES ALL THE CHEESE
GO WITH IT?
IT'S ALL GONNA GO WITH IT.
I'M GONNA PICK IT ALL UP.
OH, FRIED CHEESE
LIKE THAT.
YEP.
SEE IT'S BUBBLIN' UP THERE?
A LOT OF TIMES,
IF YOU DO IT RIGHT, YOU CAN
GET IT TO THE COUNTER IN TIME.
THE CHEESE
IS STILL BUBBLIN'.
THAT IS MONEY.
LOOK AT THAT!
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
HOW MUCH OF THAT
DO YOU GET THROUGH?
SURPRISINGLY,
ALMOST THE WHOLE THING.
NO!
YEAH.
THE STANDARD SQUEEZE
COMES DONE UP RIGHT.
(Travis) MAYONNAISE, MUSTARD,
LONG-SLICED DILL PICKLES,
A COUPLE TOMATOES.
THE LONG-SLICED DILL PICKLE--
THAT'S ALSO PART OF THE...
IT IS, AND IT'S
A REFRIGERATED PICKLE,
SO IT'S NOT ONE OF THOSE
REAL HEAVY, VINEGARY--
IT'S--IT'S MORE OF
A CRISP PICKLE TASTE THAT...
REALLY?
REALLY DUMPS OUT AT YA.
OH, IT'S GREAT.
YOU GOT ALL YOUR OPTIONS, TOO.
BACON BURGER,
MUSHROOM BURGER...
WE CAN ADD
JALAPEÑOS, AVOCADO.
I CAN HELP
WHOEVER'S NEXT TO ORDER.
AND WHEN THE SQUEEZE INN
GETS ROCKIN'...
OKAY, THAT'S AN ORDER FOR 10
RIGHT THERE AT 11:30.
10?
SO DOES TRAVIS.
THERE'S FOUR
READY TO ROLL.
THAT'S CRAZY.
SO THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
COME IN AND SLICE IT.
WATCH YOUR TOES, MAN.
IT'S HOT STUFF.
WRONG DAY
TO WEAR FLIP-FLOPS.
WHO COOKS WITH YOU?
I'LL DO ALL THE COOKIN'
BY MYSELF.
UP TO TEN HOURS A DAY NONSTOP.
I MEAN, DUDE,
YOU ARE FULL THROTTLE.
AND DON'T THINK
THIS IS EASY.
(Travis) YEAH, YOU GOTTA
REALLY CUT AND PUSH HARD.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU GOT TO GET...
(straining) GOD!
OKAY, THE BURGER...
WHERE? THE BURGER?
(man) YEP.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S HARD TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE YOU LAND IT.
I CAN'T EVEN FIND
THE BURGER UNDERNEATH IT.
I GUESS IT'S OKAY
TO MAKE A MESS HERE?
IF YOU DON'T MAKE A MESS,
YOU'RE NOT DOIN' IT RIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT DOIN' IT RIGHT--
DOESN'T HAVE THE RIGHT FLAVOR?
I THINK I GOTTA
LOOSEN 'EM UP FIRST.
AHA! THAT'S THE KEY.
COMIN' OVER HOT!
PERFECT.
YOU'RE THERE, MAN.
I MIGHT AS WELL
JUST GO HOME.
YEAH! YEAH!
YOU'RE DIALED IN.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
GO HOME.
AND EVEN IF YOU MASTER
THE MELTING OF THE CHEESE,
YOU STILL GOT TO MASTER
THE EATING OF THE CHEESE...
YOU GOT TO GRAB IT
JUST LIKE THAT.
KNOWN AT THE SQUEEZE INN
AS THE SKIRT.
NOW, YOU TOOK
YOUR SKIRT OFF.
(man laughs)
I TAKE PART OF IT OFF
AND EAT IT.
(woman)
YOU GOT TO FOLD IT IN,
AND YOU GOT TO RIP
THE SIDE A LITTLE BIT.
(Guy) NOW DO YOU EAT THE PART
THAT YOU'RE TEARING OFF?
YEAH!
HOLD THE BURGER WITH ONE HAND
AND NEVER LET IT GO
AND EAT YOUR FRIES
WITH THE OTHER HAND.
IT CAN BE A BIT MESSY.
THAT'S GOOD LIKE THAT--
MAKE A BERTHING SPOT.
THERE YOU GO.
YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
THAT THING IS MONEY.
FAST-FOOD CHAINS
ACROSS AMERICA
WANT THEIR BURGER
TO LOOK LIKE THAT...
YEAH, THEY GOT
AWAY FROM THAT.
BUT IT'S ABOUT
THE REAL DEAL, MAN.
IT IS, YEAH.
NOT BAD FOR A TOTAL NEWCOMER
TO THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
ACTUALLY, I WORKED
AT A SCHOOL FOR YEARS.
I NEVER, UH--NEVER EVEN
THOUGHT ABOUT A RESTAURANT.
BUT WHEN AN OLD ARMY BUDDY
TOLD HIM THE SQUEEZE INN
WAS UP FOR SALE,
HE DECIDED TO TAKE A CHANCE.
(Guy) DO YOU MISS SCHOOL?
NOT AT ALL.
WITHIN MONTHS, HE MASTERED
THE SQUEEZE WITH CHEESE
AND THE REST OF THE MENU, TOO,
LIKE TACOS
MADE FROM RIB EYE ROAST...
IT HAS A PRETTY PREMIUM
KIND OF MEAT.
YEAH, IT IS.
AND SMOTHERED IN CHEESE...
(woman) YAY!
THAT'S A GOOD TACO, MAN.
AND STEAK TERIYAKI
WITH A KILLER HOMEMADE SAUCE.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
AND TRAVIS IS TURNING THIS
INTO A FAMILY AFFAIR
NOW, TOO.
ALL RIGHT, THE DOUBLE?
THAT'S MY DAUGHTER MORGAN,
MY FUTURE DAUGHTER-IN-LAW KATIE.
NOW THIS IS YOUR SON?
THAT'S MY SON BRANDON.
ARE YOU GONNA TAKE OVER
THE EMPIRE SOMEDAY?
YEAH, SOMEDAY.
THE EMPIRE THING'S NO JOKE.
AND YOU KEEP WINNING
BEST DIVE RESTAURANT?
YEAH, WE HAVE
FOR FOUR YEARS IN A ROW NOW.
BEST DIVE RESTAURANT?
YEAH.
FOR THE FOOD
AND THE EXPERIENCE
OF CHOWIN' DOWN IN WHAT MIGHT
AS WELL BE A PHONE BOOTH--
WELL, A PHONE BOOTH
WITH A PATIO...
HAVE Y'ALL
BEEN HERE BEFORE?
(all) YEAH.
AND HUNDREDS
OF FANATIC REGULARS...
(man) SQUEEZE BURGER.
DOUBLE.
SQUEEZE BURGER?
A DOUBLE.
LOOK AT THE PIPES.
OF COURSE YOU CAN EAT
THE DOUBLE, MAN!
THAT'S RIGHT.
(Guy) THE SQUEEZE
WITH CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT.
'CAUSE FOR TONS OF FOLKS
AROUND SACRAMENTO,
THE SQUEEZE INN IS A HABIT
NO ONE WANTS TO BREAK.
AWESOME!
YOU GUYS HAVE THIS ATTITUDE
ABOUT STICKIN' TO WHAT'S REAL,
STICKIN' TO WHAT
YOU ALREADY DID,
STICKIN' WITH WHAT WORKS.
IF IT WORKS, YOU DON'T
WANT TO CHANGE IT.
YOU PROMISE MY DOCTOR
WON'T SEE THIS, RIGHT?
WE HAVE THAT
CONFIDENTIALITY THING--
TV HOST AND SOME DUDE
THAT'S ON--
YEAH, ROSS,
DON'T WORRY, MAN.
NEXT UP...
THIS IS KINDA LIKE
A BURGER EMPORIUM.
I'M HEADING FOR CHICAGO
FOR THE INSIDE SECRETS
OF THE INSIDE-OUT BURGER.
OH, THAT IS GREAT.
THERE'S A LOT OF FUN
IN THE BUN.
IT'S NOT OFTEN
THAT YOU FIND YOURSELF
CRUISIN' A RESIDENTIAL AREA
LOOKIN' FOR A PLACE TO EAT,
BUT THE LOCALS HERE
IN GLENVIEW, ILLINOIS,
SAY THIS IS THE SPOT.
RIGHT BEHIND GRANDMA'S HOUSE
IS THIS JOINT, AND THEY SAY
THE BURGERS ARE THE BOMB.
IT'S SO GREAT.
OH, THAT LOOKS KILLER.
THERE'S A LOT OF FUN
IN THE BUN.
PART OF GROWING UP IN
THE NORTHERN SUBURBS OF CHICAGO
IS YOU COME TO HACKNEY'S.
YOU SURE DO.
IS THAT OKAY?
AFTER 80 YEARS,
FOR FOLKS AROUND HERE,
IT'S JUST THAT SIMPLE.
NUMBER ONE SELLING ITEM ON
THE MENU HERE IS THE BURGER?
IS THE HACKNEY BURGER,
THAT'S RIGHT.
JUST THE STRAIGHT-UP BURGER?
THE STRAIGHT-UP BURGER.
AN 8-OUNCE OBLONG
THEY'VE BEEN GETTING
FROM THE SAME BUTCHER
FOR 30 YEARS.
I ORDER THE HACKNEY BURGER
EVERY TIME BECAUSE IT'S SO GOOD.
THERE'S THE INSIDE-OUT BURGER
STUFFED WITH CHEDDAR
AND BACON...
IT'S A MESS.
IT'S SO JUICY.
AND THE BLUE CHEESE BURGER
WITH THE CHEESE MIXED
INTO THE MEAT
BEFORE IT'S GRILLED,
THE PATTY MELT,
THE BRICK OF ONION RINGS
AND A HUGE MENU OF ALL KINDS
OF HOME-COOKED FAVORITES
AND HOME-BAKED DESSERTS.
PRETTY MUCH YOU CAN'T
GO WRONG WITH THE MENU.
BUT WHEN FOLKS THINK HACKNEY'S,
THE FIRST THING THEY'RE
THINKIN' IS THE BURGER.
IT'S THE BEST BURGER. IT IS.
AND HAS BEEN SINCE PROHIBITION
BACK IN THE '20s
WHEN BEBE HACKNEY
STARTED SERVING BURGERS
AT THE ILLEGAL BEER JOINT SHE
WAS RUNNING ON HER BACK PORCH.
THEY GAVE THE FOOD AWAY
IN THE EARLY DAYS.
KINDA LIKE PEANUTS
AT A BAR...
EXACTLY...
YOU COME AND DRINK THE BEER,
AND THEN WE'LL GIVE YOU
THE BURGER FOR FREE.
EXACTLY.
WOW, I WISH THAT
WAS STILL THE PROGRAM.
OKAY, SO IT'S NOT FREE ANYMORE,
BUT IT REALLY IS
A HECK OF A BURGER.
THIS IS KINDA LIKE
A BURGER EMPORIUM.
I'M JUST LETTIN'...
IT'S STUFFED. YOU GET 'EM DONE
WITH BLUE CHEESE. YOU GET 'EM
THE ORIGINAL WAY.
AND CHECK OUT
THE ORIGINAL WAY
THEY'RE STILL MAKIN'
THE INSIDE-OUT BURGER.
I MEAN, THIS IS, LIKE,
THE TECHNIQUE HERE.
THIS IS THE TECHNIQUE
THAT WE USE TO MAKE
THE INSIDE-OUT BURGER.
WHAT IS THIS--
JUST A REGULAR OLD LID
OFF OF ONE OF
THE MAYONNAISE CONTAINERS?
THIS IS
A VERY HIGH-TECH GADGET.
YES, I CAN SEE THAT.
AND WE TAKE APPROXIMATELY
HALF OF THE BURGER,
AND WE SHAPE IT OUT.
YOU GOT TO PACK IT
IN THERE A LITTLE BIT.
NEXT THING WE DO IS WE
PUT IN THE CHEDDAR CHEESE.
WE TRY TO KEEP IT A LITTLE BIT
TOWARDS THE MIDDLE
IN ORDER TO LET THE EDGES
OF THE BURGER MEET.
OTHERWISE, WHEN YOU DO
COOK IT, IT FALLS APART...
IT STARTS COMIN'
OUT THE SIDES. OKAY.
LAST--THE CHOPPED BACON.
NOW HOW MANY OF THESE BURGERS
WILL YOU MAKE?
50 MAYBE.
50?
YEAH.
WELL, YOU CAN COUNT
51 TODAY.
OKAY, 51? GOOD.
THAT'S
OUR INSIDE-OUT, RIGHT?
THAT'S OUR INSIDE-OUT.
THAT ONE'S READY TO GO.
OKAY.
NO MAYONNAISE,
MUSTARD, NOTHIN'.
THAT'S RIGHT--
JUST LETTUCE AND TOMATO.
OH, MAN.
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
A LITTLE CRUNCH
OF THE BACON...
GOOD MEAT.
TONS OF FLAVOR.
OH, THAT IS GREAT.
SOFT AND CHEESY
ON THE INSIDE.
IT TASTES BACON-Y.
OR MAYBE YOU'D RATHER GO
WITH THE BLUE CHEESE.
WE HAVE A LOT
OF BLUE CHEESE.
WE TAKE OUR HACKNEY BURGER--
8 OUNCES--
WE THROW ABOUT ANOTHER OUNCE
OF CHEESE INSIDE
AND MIX IT UP.
AND MIX IT ALL TOGETHER?
BUST IT OUT.
OKAY, TAKE
ABOUT AN OUNCE.
AND THEN IT JUST
ALL MELTS INSIDE THERE.
WHAT ELSE GOES WITH THIS?
NO, IT'S JUST
THE HACKNEY BURGER...
THAT'S IT--THE HACKNEY BURGER
WITH BLUE CHEESE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ONCE IT'S MIXED,
IT'S SLAPPED ON THE GRILL
AND EVEN MORE BLUE CHEESE
IS MELTED ON THE TOP.
MMM.
ALL THE BLUE CHEESE...
THAT IS RICH.
DON'T GET EMOTIONAL
ABOUT IT.
WOW!
WHY NOT? THEY EVEN BAKE
THEIR OWN BUNS...
THE BREAD'S OFF THE HOOK.
SMELL.
AND THE SPECIAL DARK RYE
THEY'VE BEEN SERVING
ON THE SIGNATURE HACKNEY BURGER
FOREVER.
MMM.
IT'S A TRADITION,
'CAUSE IT--THERE'S--
YOU GO TO HACKNEY'S,
AND YOU GET THE HACKNEY BURGER.
AND TO GO WITH IT,
A HUGE BRICK OF ONION RINGS.
SO THIS IS BURGERS PLUS.
THIS IS BURGERS PLUS.
TELL ME THAT'S NOT
SIX EXTRA DAYS AT THE GYM.
YEAH.
THEIR FRIED ONION RINGS--
THEY'RE FANTASTIC.
THE ONION RING LOAF
STARTS HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY. NOW WHO MADE
THIS RECIPE UP?
IT WAS
ON A FRIDAY FISH FRY
BACK IN THE EARLY '50s,
AND ON A CERTAIN
FRIDAY NIGHT,
THEY RAN OUT
OF LAKE PERCH,
AND A CUSTOMER
HAD ORDERED IT,
AND CARMEN, WHO WAS A COOK
HERE, SAID, "IN THE MEANTIME,
I'M GONNA FIX UP SOMETHING
THAT YOU'RE NEVER GONNA FORGET."
SO SHE CAME, SHE BREADED UP
SOME ONION RINGS,
SHE FRIED IT UP
IN A BASKET,
AND THEN THAT WAS THE BIRTH
OF THE ONION RINGS.
IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'VE DONE IT BEFORE.
YEAH, NO, THIS IS--
GRANDMA MADE US
PASS THIS TEST.
YOU KNOW, WE HAD TO MAKE SURE
WE COULD DUMP A GOOD...
HEY, HEY, HEY!
WHERE YOU GOIN' WITH THAT?
OH, WAIT. SORRY, SORRY,
SORRY.
TAKIN' IT ANYWHERE.
OH, MAN.
JUST LIKE DECADES AGO,
AND THAT'S THE WHOLE IDEA
WITH EVERYTHING HERE.
SO MANY PLACES
CHANGE AFTER A WHILE...
YEAH.
AND THIS ONE HAS STAYED TRUE
TO THEIR ORIGINAL CONCEPT.
IT'S A JOINT.
IT'S ABOUT THE FOOD.
IT'S ABOUT BEING HERE.
IT'S ABOUT THE PEOPLE.
IT'S JUST--
IT'S NICE. IT FEELS GOOD.
OH, YEAH. TASTES GOOD, TOO.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THAT'S ALL-AMERICAN,
BABY.
THIS IS GREAT.
UP NEXT,
AN INDIANA INSTITUTION WHERE
THE BURGERS START AS STEAK.
I MEAN, LOOK AT
THE MARBLING ON THAT.
AND THEY'LL TOP 'EM
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
I WANT TO GO HOME.
I WANT MY MOM.
I'M HERE
IN WEST LAFAYETTE, INDIANA,
YOU KNOW, THE HOME
OF PURDUE UNIVERSITY,
AND TWO THINGS COME TO MIND--
ONE--HOW DID THE BOILERMAKERS
REALLY GET THEIR NAME?
AND TWO--WHAT IN THE WORLD
WILL THEY BE SERVING
AT A PLACE CALLED
THE TRIPLE XXX DRIVE-IN?
TRIPLE XXX--THIS IS READY TO GO,
'CAUSE I DON'T SEE FLOUR, RIGHT?
OKAY, ONE ANSWER IS BURGERS,
BURGERS AND BURGERS.
(Guy) IS IT
A GOOD HAMBURGER?
LOOK AT THAT BITE!
THE BURGERS ARE EXCELLENT.
AS FOR PURDUE...
WITHOUT TRIPLE XXX,
PURDUE WOULD BE INCOMPLETE.
THE BOILERMAKERS' NICKNAME
MAY HAVE COME FROM THE FAME
OF THEIR ENGINEERING
INSTRUCTION IN THE 1800s.
AS FOR THE FAME
OF THEIR ATHLETES,
IT'S A LOCAL OBSESSION.
CHECK OUT THE WALL
AT THE TRIPLE XXX
WHERE THEY'VE EVEN GOT BURGERS
NAMED FOR FORMER PLAYERS
LIKE THE BERNIE FLOWERS
WITH A HUNK OF ONION
OR THE DREW BREES
BREAKFAST SPECIAL.
I WOULD CHOOSE TRIPLE XXX
OVER FAST FOOD ANYTIME.
BECAUSE FOR MORE THAN 75 YEARS,
THE TRIPLE XXX
HAS BEEN WAY MORE
THAN THE AVERAGE BURGER JOINT.
THIS IS A TRADITION THAT, LIKE,
EVERYBODY KNOWS IT.
THEY KNOW THE BUILDING OF ORANGE
AND BLACK THAT'S, LIKE, AN ICON.
AND OWNERS
GREG AND CARRIE EHRESMAN
ARE COMMITTED
TO KEEPIN' IT THAT WAY.
WE DON'T CALL 'EM HAMBURGERS.
THEY'RE STEAK BURGERS.
STEAK BURGERS.
CHOPPED STEAKS.
THEY'RE NEVER HAMBURGERS.
THEY'RE CALLED
CHOPPED STEAKS.
SINCE 1929.
ALL CUT AND GROUND FRESH
RIGHT HERE,
AND NOT JUST
ANY STEAK, EITHER.
TOP CHOICE SIRLOIN BUTT.
I MEAN, LOOK AT
THE MARBLING ON THAT.
YOU CAN CUT THAT
INTO STEAK JUST BY ITSELF.
THAT WE HAVE DONE...
I IMAGINE YOU HAVE.
AND IT COOKS QUITE WELL.
I'VE SEEN ENOUGH
CUT, CUT, CUT.
I WANT TO SEE
GRIND, GRIND, GRIND.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
IT LOOKS LIKE WE ARE MAKING
A TON OF MULTICOLORED SPAGHETTI.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A NICE MIX
BETWEEN, UH--BETWEEN
FAT-TO-MEAT RATIO...
IT'S A REAL NICE BLEND.
NICE, RED, DEEP,
RICH COLOR.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
HE TURNS IT ALL
INTO PATTIES
THE SAME WAY IT'S BEEN DONE
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
WHEN DID BEN FRANKLIN
INVENT THIS ONE?
(laughs)
THIS IS THE HOLLYMATIC.
THE HOLLYMATIC SUPER 54.
WHAT YEAR
WAS THIS THING MADE?
1954.
NO.
YES WAY.
1954...
I DIDN'T SAY "NO WAY."
SO IF I DON'T SAY "NO WAY,"
YOU CAN'T SAY "YES WAY"...
YES WAY.
'CAUSE THEN IT
MAKES YOU SOUND LIKE...
LET'S RESHOOT THAT.
IT'S WARM-UP HERE, OKAY.
RESHOOT THAT.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
SO... NO WAY.
YEAH!
NO!
NO.
(men laughing)
THAT'S WHEN YOU...
OH, I MISSED IT!
I MISSED MY CUE.
THAT'S WHERE YOU SAY,
"YES WAY."
IT SOUNDS AS OLD AS IT LOOKS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE IT'S JUST RIGHT
ON THE EDGE OF BREAKING.
IT DOES, DOESN'T IT?
BUT IT GETS THE JOB DONE.
YOU TAKE THREE AT A TIME.
I FEEL LIKE LUCILLE BALL.
(laughs) PULL IT!
NOW THERE'S
YOUR THIRD ONE THERE.
NOW YOU'RE BACK
IN RHYTHM.
THERE YOU GO.
SORTA LIKE
MEAT POKER CHIPS.
YEAH!
I'M ALL IN.
ALL IN.
AND SO IS GREG.
HE CAN'T REMEMBER A TIME
WHEN HE WASN'T HANGIN' OUT
AT THE TRIPLE XXX--
AS A CUSTOMER GROWING UP...
DAD ALWAYS SAT
IN THE CORNER AT NUMBER 27,
AND THEN IT KINDA
WENT DOWN THE LINE.
WITH HIS WIFE HERE
WHEN THEY WERE DATING,
FINALLY HIS PARENTS
BUYING THE PLACE,
HIM WORKING WITH THEM,
THEN TAKING OVER WITH CARRIE
EIGHT YEARS AGO.
HOW ARE THEY DOIN'
RUNNIN' THIS PLACE
SINCE YOU LEFT?
I HAVEN'T LEFT!
YOU HAVEN'T REALLY LEFT. I KNOW
YOU COME IN AND GRIND THE MEAT.
THE BEST THING THEY HAVE IS
THEIR DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
THE SECRET TO THEIR BURGERS IS
SOMETHING TOTALLY
OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
MORE FLOUR. MORE FLOUR.
MORE FLOUR.
DRAG A LITTLE UP.
OKAY, DRAG A LITTLE UP.
ALL RIGHT, PUT HER
DOWN THERE. WHALE ON IT.
OKAY.
PUT HER ON THE GRILL.
BEAUTIFUL.
OKAY, THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT. ON THE GRILL.
THEN YOU GO LIKE THAT?
YEP. JUST A TOUCH OF OIL.
JUST A TOUCH OF OIL.
YOU'RE DOIN' GOOD.
IF YOU NEED A RUBDOWN,
WE'LL CALL THE PEOPLE IN.
OKAY, THERE WE GO.
SEE, I LOVE THAT.
I GOTTA TRY THAT.
THIS IS
THE COMING-OF-AGE BURGER.
AS A KID, I ALWAYS SAT UP
TO THE COUNTER WITH DAD.
HE WOULD HAVE THIS BIG,
FAT DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER...
OKAY.
AND I ALWAYS THOUGHT, MAN,
WHENEVER I GET BIG ENOUGH,
THAT'S WHEN I GET THAT.
WHENEVER I'M A BIG GUY.
WHENEVER I'M A BIG GUY, I'M
THERE. THAT'S WHAT I GOTTA GET.
BARNEY ONE DAY DECIDES--
WHO IS THE COOK AT THE TIME--
DECIDES THAT I'M READY
FOR THE DOUBLE CHEESE.
IT'S TIME.
SO HE MAKES IT FOR ME
AND BRINGS IT OUT
HIMSELF
AND JUST LOOKS AT ME
WITH A BIG GRIN ON HIS FACE,
AND HE SAID,
"THERE YOU GO,"
AND HERE WE ARE.
AND THAT WAS IT.
THAT WAS IT.
DOUBLE CHEESE.
CHEERS.
YOU GOT IT, BROTHA.
ALL RIGHT.
OHH-OHH.
THAT'S A GOOD BURGER.
NOW BARNEY HIMSELF
WASN'T A DOUBLE-CHEESE GUY,
SO IF YOU ORDER
THE BARNEY BURGER,
YOU'RE GETTIN' THIS ONE.
BARNEY LOVED TO HAVE
A THICK WHITE ONION
CUT RAW.
BUT YOU CAN'T
DO THAT TO ME, RIGHT?
MOST PEOPLE CAN'T
HANDLE THAT,
SO WE GO WITH
THE GRILLED ONIONS.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
OR YOU CAN HAVE A BURGER
WITH YOUR BREAKFAST.
YOU WANT TO PUT GRAVY
ON THE POTATOES
OF THE DREW BREES
JUST LIKE THAT,
LAY IT ON THERE.
THAT GOES BACK IN,
AND THERE'S
YOUR DREW BREES SPECIAL.
AND CHECK OUT
THE DUANE PURVIS BURGER.
PEANUT BUTTER.
GET A BIG SLAB OF THAT
AND JUST TAKE IT,
AND YOU JUST LAY IT
ON THERE.
THAT MUCH?
NICE--WELL, YOU GOT
TO HAVE A TASTE.
WE GOT TO PUT TOMATOES.
WE GOT TO PUT
SOME PICKLES ON IT,
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF LETTUCE
AND SOME ONION--
FRESH-CUT WHITE ONION.
HAVE YOU EATEN THIS?
IT'S A LOVE--
YOU EITHER LOVE IT OR DON'T
LIKE IT, AND I'M A--I'M...
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT.
HE LOVES IT.
I DON'T CARE FOR IT.
I ENVY YOU
FOR THE FIRST BITE.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S GONNA BE GREAT.
THEN GO AHEAD.
NO. HA-HA!
NO, THIS IS YOURS.
I ABSOLUTELY
DON'T ENJOY THAT AT ALL.
THAT'S--
I WANT TO GO HOME.
I WANT MY MOM.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
CAN GREG REDEEM HIMSELF?
PORK CHOP SANDWICH THAT IS
JUST RIGHT NEXT DOOR TO HEAVEN.
IT IS GONNA TAKE
SOME KILLER PORK TENDERLOIN
AND A WHOLE LOT
OF ANGER MANAGEMENT.
THE TRIPLE XXX
HAS BEEN A LOCAL HANGOUT
IN WEST LAFAYETTE, INDIANA,
SINCE 1929.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
THESE FUNNY COUNTERS--
THIS THING?
IT'S GREAT.
'CAUSE YOU HAVE
TO SAY HI TO PEOPLE.
WELL, SURE.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T--YOU END UP
SITTIN' RIGHT NEXT TO SOMEONE,
AND IT'S NOT LIKE YOU CAN JUST
SIT THERE ON A NEW YORK SUBWAY.
AND OWNERS
GREG AND CARRIE EHRESMAN
ARE KEEPING
THEIR REGULARS HAPPY
WITH THEIR
OFF-THE-HOOK BURGERS.
I MEAN, IT'S THE FACT
THAT YOU GET TO SIT HERE
IN THIS SEAT AND WATCH
THAT FAST-FOOD PLACE SUFFER!
IF YOU DON'T GO HERE
AS A PURDUE STUDENT,
THEN YOU'RE DOIN'
SOMETHING WRONG.
WHERE DID THE NAME
"TRIPLE XXX" COME FROM?
THAT'S A LONG STORY.
(Greg)
BRAND OF ROOT BEER.
OLDEST BRAND OF ROOT BEER
IN THE UNITED STATES.
IN THE '20s, THERE WERE
100 TRIPLE XXX FRANCHISES
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
THAT ENDED YEARS AGO,
BUT THIS PLACE KEPT
THE NAME AND THE ROOT BEER.
IT HAS
THAT SARSAPARILLA...
IT'S NOT AS SWEET.
YEAH, IT'S GOT
MORE BITE IN IT.
AT THE TRIPLE XXX, THERE'S
NO BREAKING FROM TRADITION...
(Greg) EXACT SAME MACHINE.
WITH EVERYTHING,
NOT JUST THE BURGERS.
YOU COME TO INDIANA,
YOU GOT TO HAVE TENDERLOIN.
(Guy) YOU GOT
TO HAVE TENDERLOIN!
THAT'S RIGHT.
PORK TENDERLOIN--BREADED,
DEEP-FRIED, BEAT UP,
HOWEVER YOU DO IT, YOU GOT
TO HAVE A PORK TENDERLOIN
WHEN YOU COME TO INDIANA.
GREG STARTS BY CUTTING
A PORK TENDERLOIN INTO CUTLETS.
NOW COMES THE FUN PART--
SOLID MAPLE.
IS THIS A STRESS-RELIEF
PROGRAM FOR YOU?
OH, YEAH.
REALLY?
OH, THIS IS AWESOME.
YOU DOWN THERE ENCOURAGING
PEOPLE TO EAT MORE PORK?
IF YOU'VE HAD A BAD DAY,
COME UP HERE AND DO THIS.
OKAY.
YOU'LL FEEL A LOT BETTER.
WHALE AWAY.
PERFECT.
SO IT'S JUST GETTIN'
IT OUT ENOUGH...
THAT'S IT.
BEFORE IT TEARS IT APART.
YOU DON'T WANT TO TEAR IT.
YOU DON'T WANT IT TOO THIN.
RIGHT THERE IS PERFECT.
SEE, I THINK YOU WERE
A LITTLE BIT GENTLER THAN MINE.
I TOOK MINE A LITTLE BIT
FURTHER, BUT THAT WORKS?
YOU WERE MAYBE A LITTLE
MORE FRUSTRATED THAN I WAS.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHY?
'CAUSE YOU GOT TO GO FIRST.
THE PORK GETS GRILLED UP
EXACTLY LIKE THE BURGERS...
GRILL JUST LIKE THAT,
AND DROP IT RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
AND SERVED UP WITH
A TOASTED BUN AND NOTHING ELSE.
IT'S JUST VERY PURE.
THE FLOUR AND THE FAT...
JUST KINDA SEALS IT
ALL UP...
YEAH.
AND KEEPS
THE JUICE IN IT.
I LIKE IT.
IF YOU'RE GONNA BE
ANYWHERE NEAR PURDUE,
THE TRIPLE XXX IS BY FAR
THE BEST FOOD YOU'LL FIND.
THE PORK, THE BURGERS,
EVEN YOUR BASIC BREAKFAST.
THE GROUP OVER THERE WAS
ALL BREAKFAST AND PANCAKES.
YOU'RE ALL OMELETS.
THAT WHOLE CREW
OVER THERE WAS ALL...
WE'RE BEEF AND PORK.
YEAH, THE BIG COUNTRY!
THE BEST TIME
IS WHEN THAT RAIL
IS FROM HERE TO HERE
AND IS JAMMED UP,
TICKETS ARE STACKIN'
ON THE END,
PEOPLE ARE WALKIN'
IN THE DOOR.
THAT'S THE BEST.
IT IS--IT'S A RIOT.
IT'S A LOT OF FUN.
IT IS...
NO WAY!
OH, YEAH!
'CAUSE WHEN I SAY "NO WAY,"
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
"WAY."
I GOT MY THREE "NO WAYS"
ON YOU.
FINALLY, YEAH.
AND SHE KEEPS GOIN',
"OH, DANG IT."
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS
WE GOT TO HIT.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
'CAUSE ALL THAT'S GONNA DO
IS BURN MY MOUTH,
AND YOU KNOW
IT'S GONNA BURN MY MOUTH,
AND ALL YOU WANT TO DO
IS LAUGH ABOUT IT,
'CAUSE IT BURNS MY MOUTH. YEAH.
OHH. OH, GOD!
(Travis) THAT'S HOT.
(radio static)