HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
TO AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP--OUR OWN
TRIPLE-D TAKE ON BARBECUE--
OH, MAN.
A CALIFORNIA JOINT WHERE MAKING
THEIR OWN HOT SAUCE
MEANS ROASTING
THEIR OWN PEPPERS.
THESE ARE WICKED.
AND GET A LOAD
OF THEIR MIXING SYSTEM.
I'M GONNA BUY YOU
A BIGGER BUCKET.
A TEXAS TRADITION
WHERE THE BRISKETS HAD 'EM
LININ' UP FOR ALMOST 60 YEARS.
(Guy) WOW.
THE BEST.
AND HOMEMADE SAUSAGE.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND THE RIBS ARE LIKE SOMETHING
OUT OF "THE FLINTSTONES."
GOOD STUFF.
AND A NORTH CAROLINA DRIVE-IN
WHERE THE PULLED PORK
IS THE BOMB.
WHEN YOU COME TO CHARLOTTE,
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME.
AND THEY'RE DOING
BARBECUE CHICKEN
LIKE YOU'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
DUDE, THAT'S
OUT OF BOUNDS RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
VENICE, CALIFORNIA--
YOU GOTTA LOVE THE WEATHER,
THE BEACH, THE CHARACTERS,
THE FOOD.
BUT I GOTTA BE HONEST WITH YA,
WHEN I'M IN VENICE BEACH,
CALIFORNIA,
I'M NOT THINKING
ABOUT SOUTHERN-STYLE BARBECUE
UNTIL I FOUND THIS JOINT--
BABY BLUES BAR-B-Q. WOW.
"BIG BLUE," "BLUE DEVIL,"
"ACE IN THE SLEEVE,"
"THREE KINGS," "MASON DIXON"--
THAT'S GOOD.
WHO CAME UP
WITH ALL THE NAMES?
WE JUST PLAYED AROUND WITH IT.
WE HAD SOME WAITRESSES DID.
WE HEARD THE OWNERS
WERE SMOKIN' HOT,
SO WE HAD TO COME IN
AND TRY.
AT BABY BLUES,
OWNERS DANNY FISCHER
AND RICK McCARTHY
ARE DOING TOTALLY OFF-THE-HOOK,
ONE-OF-A-KIND
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA BARBECUE...
YOU HEARD ME--
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA BARBECUE.
YOU GUYS KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
WE DO BARBECUE OUT HERE
ON THE WEST COAST--
IT'S CALLED GRILLING.
PEOPLE DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THEY THINK WE'RE REINVENTING
THE WHEEL HERE,
'CAUSE THEY'RE
JUST NOT USED TO IT OUT HERE.
THIS SEEMS NATURAL TO US,
AND IT'S SHOCKING
TO OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEREVER RIBS ARE OFFERED,
I USUALLY ORDER BABY BACK RIBS
AND JUDGE A PLACE BY THAT,
AND THESE ARE THE BEST.
OKAY.
WHEN PEOPLE ASK US
WHAT KIND OF BARBECUE IT IS--
IT'S REALLY A HYBRID BARBECUE.
WELL, DRY-RUB IS TEXAS...
YEAH.
VINEGAR-BASED
IS NORTH CAROLINA--
IS THE CAROLINAS...
YEP.
RIGHT.
AND THEN RED SAUCE
IN GENERAL KINDA GETS
THAT KANSAS CITY SPIN
IN IT.
YEAH.
SO, YEAH. NO, I'M DOWN
WITH YOU, MAN.
I FEEL YOUR PAIN.
BY PULLING THE BEST FROM EACH,
THESE TWO EAST COAST
TRANSPLANTS
HAVE PUT TOGETHER A MENU
THAT'S A VIRTUAL TOUR
OF GREAT BARBECUE.
PRETTY DAMN GOOD BARBECUE...
I'M TELLIN' YA.
FOR CALIFORNIA.
THEY'VE GOT BABY BACK RIBS...
OH, MAN. I MEAN,
THIS IS TENDER-TENDER.
YEAH.
GREAT FLAVOR, MAN.
THEY'VE GOT MEMPHIS-STYLE RIBS.
IT'S JUST THAT THERE'S
A TEXTURE, THERE'S A FLAVOR.
IT'S DEEPER. IT'S MEATIER.
IT'S--MMM.
OKAY, I'M GONNA GO
TAKE A LITTLE NAP.
THEY'VE GOT TEXAS BEEF RIBS.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THIS MUST HAVE BEEN, LIKE,
PAUL BUNYAN'S BLUE OX.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
LOTS AND LOTS OF MEAT
ON THE RIBS.
(man) YEAH,
IT'S ALL MEAT.
THAT'S ONE RIB.
THAT'S ONE RIB...
BUT THE REAL ACE
UP THEIR SLEEVE...
I'M EATING A PORK SANDWICH.
IS THE PULLED PORK.
IT'S WHAT I ALWAYS GET.
I HAVEN'T EVEN TRIED
ANYTHING ELSE.
THE PULLED PORK
IS KIND OF A STAPLE FOR US.
WE MARINATE--
THIS IS A DRY RUB.
THIS HAS GOT ABOUT 19 HERBS
AND SPICES IN IT.
ONCE IT'S TOTALLY COVERED,
THE PORK SPENDS A NIGHT
IN THE COOLER.
WHAT'S THE IDEA,
BESIDES JUST LETTING IT SIT
IN THE COOLER OR THE WALK-IN?
NOTHIN'.
PENETRATING THE MEAT,
THAT'S THE ONLY--
BUT YOU COULD'VE LET IT
PENETRATE JUST SITTING
LIKE THIS.
IT WILL, BUT IT--FOR 24 HOURS,
IT'S GONNA REALLY GET IN THERE,
AND IT'S GONNA START
TO FORM A BIT OF A CRUST,
AND THAT'S THE BEST THING.
YEAH, HOW LONG
ARE THEY GONNA SMOKE?
ABOUT 16-19 HOURS.
A PORK BUTT?
16-18 HOURS...
16-18 HOURS?
WE DO A REAL SLOW,
LOW HEAT--
ABOUT 250 DEGREES.
CAN YOU EVEN BRING IT
OUT OF THERE,
OR DOES IT
JUST COMPLETELY JUST--
IT FALLS APART.
ORDINARILY WE'D SAY,
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT.
WE'RE NOT TELLING YOU.
WE'VE HAD OUR LITTLE THINGS
WE DON'T TELL YOU.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU
THE ONE SECRET WE DO IS THIS--
IS WE DO THE GUINNESS.
(cap clatters)
SEE THAT?
THAT WAS PRETTY GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FILL THIS
WITH GUINNESS,
AND THEN WHAT WE'RE
GONNA DO IS,
ANY REMAINDER WE'RE GONNA HAVE,
WE'RE GONNA POUR WATER IN THERE.
AND THE REASON FOR THAT
IS 'CAUSE THE ALCOHOL ALONE
WILL BURN OFF LIKE THAT.
ONCE THEY'RE DONE SMOKING,
DANNY AND RICK JUST PULL IT
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
YOU CAN--YOU CAN SEE
HOW THEY'RE GONNA FALL
RIGHT OFF THE BONE RIGHT HERE,
AND THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE GOING FOR.
IT'S STILL PINK. YOU STILL GOT
THE SMOKE RINGS IN THERE...
RIGHT.
BUT YET IT'S GONNA BE TENDER
ENOUGH TO FALL OFF THE BONE.
DIP A LITTLE IN THAT SAUCE.
THIS IS KINDA LIKE
PULLED PORK
MEETS AU JUS FRENCH DIP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MMM. THAT DOES NOT SUCK
AT ALL.
YOU JUST KEEP WORKING.
I'LL EAT.
RICK AND DANNY OPENED
THIS PLACE 2 1/2 YEARS AGO--
TWO EAST COAST TRANSPLANTS WHO
GREW UP IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
MY FATHER HAD BARBECUE
RESTAURANTS FOR 25 YEARS,
SO THAT'S
WHAT I GREW UP DOING.
AND HIS FAMILY HAD
SOUL FOOD RESTAURANTS.
MY BROTHER HAD IT.
SO SOME OF THESE RECIPES
HAVE DERIVED...
YEAH.
FROM YOUR FATHER'S RESTAURANT,
AND SOME FROM YOURS...
EXACTLY.
AND THEN YOU GUYS THROW YOUR OWN
LITTLE CALIFORNIA TWEAK ON IT.
EXACTLY.
LIKE THEIR
KILLER MAC AND CHEESE.
I'VE SEEN PEOPLE JUST ABOUT CRY
WHEN THEY COME HERE
AND THERE'S
NO MACARONI AND CHEESE.
(Guy) OKAY, THERE'S FOUR CHEESES
IN THE MAC AND CHEESE?
YES. IT'S A 4-CHEESE
MAC AND CHEESE.
NICE AND CREAMY--
LOT OF BIG FLAVOR.
AND CHECK OUT THE GRILLED CORN.
WE USE COTIJA CHEESE
ON OUR GRILLED CORN.
IT'S GRILLED CORN
WITH A CHIPOTLE-POBLANO BUTTER,
COTIJA CHEESE AND A LIME.
THAT'S TIGHT.
OH, OH, OH, OH...
IS THAT WHAT THIS IS?
THAT'S WHAT THAT IS.
THAT'S THE BUTTER?
AND THEN YOU TAKE THAT
AND PUT THAT ON THE CORN?
PUT IT ON THE CORN...
AND THEN YOU SPRINKLE
ON THE CHEESE.
WITH A LITTLE COTIJA CHEESE
AND A LITTLE LIME.
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
HOW ABOUT THIS CORN?
I DIDN'T HAVE IT.
OH, IT'S GREAT.
HAVE YOU TRIED THIS YET?
WELL, NO. I WAS--
HELP YOURSELF.
OKAY.
TAKE A BITE OUT OF IT.
TAKE A BIG OL' BITE.
(laughs)
LOOK AT HIM.
WOW. THAT WAS MORE--
THAT WAS MORE THAN A BITE.
I'LL GET YOU A NEW ORDER.
IT'S YOURS NOW.
I'M GONNA GET A CHAIR.
BUT WHAT REALLY SETS
THIS PLACE APART
IS THEIR TOTALLY
OFF-THE-HOOK HOMEMADE SAUCE.
IT'S DANGEROUS, BUT IT
HAS A GOOD FLAVOR.
SO THIS IS BASICALLY
OUR TRIPLE-X BUCKET.
YOU SEE, "XXX." IT'S
DESIGNATED ONLY FOR THAT,
BECAUSE THE REMNANTS, EVEN
NO MATTER HOW MUCH YOU CLEAN IT,
IT'S GONNA BE HOT. YOU CAN'T
PUT ANYTHING ELSE IN THERE.
GARLIC GOES DOWN.
THE GARLIC GOES IN.
THE PINEAPPLE IN.
YEP.
NOW WE HAVE MYSTERY CANS
OF CHIPOTLES.
CHIPOTLE PEPPERS.
THEN COMES THE REAL HEAT.
SO NOW IT'S
THE SCOTCH BONNET TIME?
WE'RE GONNA ROAST
5 POUNDS OF SCOTCH BONNET.
THESE ARE WICKED.
YEAH, THEY'RE NICE.
YEAH.
ALONG WITH THE SCOTCH BONNETS
ARE POBLANOS AND SERRANOS.
(Danny) THE POBLANOS WE TRY
AND BLACKEN AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE,
FOR THE REASON, WE WANT TO BURN
AS MUCH SKIN OFF AS POSSIBLE.
THEY STILL SCARE ME, MAN.
I'M GONNA SAY YEAH,
IT'S STILL SCARY,
BUT IT'S LESS SCARY.
THE PEPPERS GET PURéED AND THEN
ADDED TO THE REST OF THE MIX.
(Guy) NOW THE MAGIC--
"I'M NOT GONNA TELL YOU WHAT"
SYRUP GOES IN.
(Danny) RIGHT.
I MEAN, IS THERE
SOMETHING ABOUT--
JUST POUR IT IN. JEEZ...
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE HOT SAUCE.
IT'S A CAYENNE PEPPER SAUCE.
THE PEPPERED--
THE PEPPERED HOT SAUCE.
SO SOMETHING LIKE
YOU'D USE FOR BUFFALO WINGS...
EXACTLY.
RIGHT.
STUFF LIKE THAT.
NOW ALL THIS STUFF
HAS TO GET MIXED TOGETHER,
AND RICK AND DANNY DO IT
OLD-SCHOOL.
AND HERE THEY ARE WITH THEIR
MAGICAL BUCKET SYSTEM.
(vocalizing in rhythm)
(laughing)
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M GONNA DO
FOR YOU GUYS?
I'M GONNA BUY YOU
A BIGGER BUCKET.
NICE.
A BIGGER BUCKET--
WHY DIDN'T WE THINK OF THAT?
WHY--I MEAN, THAT WHOLE CONCEPT
OF A BIGGER BUCKET.
ONCE THE SAUCE HAS BEEN SITTING
FOR AT LEAST A DAY,
IT GETS STRAINED.
WHAT WE'LL DO IS WE'LL ONLY
STRAIN WHAT WE NEED RIGHT NOW,
'CAUSE WE NEED IT IMMEDIATELY...
OH, REALLY?
BECAUSE WE'D RATHER IT GO
48 HOURS IF NOT MORE.
SO IT DOES MELLOW OUT
A LITTLE BIT--
ROUNDS OUT A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
GOSH, THAT WOULD BE
GOOD ON... ANYTHING.
IT'S NOT GOOD TO EAT 'EM
ON THE WAY, IS IT?
BETWEEN THE SAUCE
AND EVERY-WHICH-WAY
KIND OF BARBECUE,
BABY BLUES IS ROCKIN'!
I CAN'T TALK--IT'S SO GOOD.
THEY HAVE KOOL-AID HERE.
THEY HAVE BANANA PUDDING.
IT JUST MAKES ME FEEL LIKE,
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU WERE YOUNGER
AND THEY HAD--YOUR GRANDMA'S
HOUSE OR SOMETHING.
AND NEW CUSTOMERS
ARE WALKIN' IN EVERY DAY.
YOU GOT YOUR BABY BACKS.
YOU GOT YOUR TEXAS BEEF RIB.
YOU GOT YOUR MEMPHIS RIBS
AND YOU GOT YOUR CHICKEN.
THERE WE GO. WOW!
HE'S REALLY GETTIN'
INTO IT.
THIS IS SO GOOD.
STAY RIGHT THERE, 'CAUSE I WANT
TO TAKE YOUR PICTURE.
WORTH EVERY BITE.
I THINK I'M GONNA TAKE THIS HOME
AND HANG IT ON THE WALL.
SHE'S NOT CRYING 'CAUSE SHE
DOESN'T LIKE THE PLATE.
SHE'S CRYING
'CAUSE SHE DIDN'T GET ANY.
THESE GOT SOME BITE,
GOT SOME CHEW.
HEY, WHERE YOU GOING?
WHERE YOU BEEN?
HEY, I WAS--
THERE'S GIRLS OVER THERE.
THERE WERE GIRLS
OVER THERE.
NEXT WE'RE HEADING
DEEP INTO TEXAS,
WHERE YOU KNOW
THE BARBECUE'S THE BOMB...
THE BEST.
WHEN A PLACE LIKE THIS DRAWS
A CROWD THAT LOOKS LIKE THIS.
THIS IS THE BEST BARBECUE
IN CENTRAL TEXAS.
THAT'S WHY I'VE GOT
MY MOUTH FULL.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
ABOUT DOING
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES,"
IS I GET TO VISIT PLACES
THAT I'M A REAL FAN OF.
NOW, I LOVE BARBECUE,
AND I OWN
A COUPLE BARBECUE RESTAURANTS
IN CALIFORNIA.
SO WHEN I GET A CHANCE
TO TRY SOME FAMOUS BRISKET
AT LOUIE MUELLER'S
IN TAYLOR, TEXAS--
WELL, TODAY'S GONNA BE
A GOOD DAY. WOW!
OH, OH.
IT'S TO DIE FOR.
557--BRISKET.
THAT'S THE BEST BARBECUE
IN CENTRAL TEXAS.
THAT'S WHY I'VE GOT
MY MOUTH FULL.
BOBBY MUELLER HAS BEEN RUNNING
THIS PLACE FOR 33 YEARS.
THIS IS THE SIGNAL?
THAT'S THE SIGNAL.
IF THEY DRIVE BY AND SEE THIS,
THIS MEANS IT'S GO TIME?
WE'RE HERE.
IT'S GO TIME.
BOBBY'S DAD, LOUIE, STARTED
THE WHOLE THING BACK IN 1949.
ONE BONE...
FOLKS HAVE BEEN LINING UP
EVER SINCE.
WE MOVED HERE IN '63, SO I BEEN
HERE SINCE EIGHTH GRADE.
YOU CAN'T GET
A GOOD MENU BOARD ANYMORE.
NO, YOU CAN'T.
BUT FOLKS KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE HERE FOR--
LEGENDARY BRISKET,
HOMEMADE SAUSAGE...
(Guy) THAT'S PHENOMENAL, HUH?
PORK RIBS, BEEF RIBS...
ONE RIB--A FULL MEAL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOOD STUFF.
AND ANYTHING ELSE
BOBBY THROWS IN THE PIT.
FIRST LAW IS GET
YOUR "FARS" GOIN'--FIRES GOIN'.
DID YOU JUST GIVE
ME A "FAR"?
NO "FAR"--YEAH, FIRE.
YOU GIVE ME A FAR, A FIRE,
I'LL TAKE EITHER ONE.
BUT I APPRECIATE YOUR CHANGIN'
IT FOR US GRINGOS OVER HERE.
AND WHERE'S THE WOOD
COME FROM?
TREES.
NO, IT COMES--
OH, IS THAT HOW
THIS IS GONNA GO TODAY?
THIS PIT WAS BUILT
HOW LONG AGO?
MM, THIS WAS BUILT IN,
UH, WELL, '59.
BUT IT'S NOT JUST THE PIT.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS DONE THE OLD WAY.
JUST LOOK AT THE PLACE.
WALKING IN IS
LIKE WALKING BACK IN TIME.
YOUR FOOD COMES ON
A BUTCHER PAPER-COVERED TRAY.
A LITTLE BITE
OF THAT FOR Y'ALL.
AND BOBBY'S
RIGHT-HAND-MAN LANCE,
WHO JOINED SIX YEARS AGO,
SEEMS LIKE HE'S BEEN HERE
FROM THE START.
SO YOU KEEP CHUMMIN' THE CROWD
WITH THESE LITTLE NIBBLES.
YES, SIR.
FIRST HIT'S FREE, HUH?
THAT'S IT.
THAT IS GOOD.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED
THE SAUCE.
"I DON'T WANT ANY SAUCE.
YOUR BRISKET'S
GOOD ENOUGH WITHOUT IT."
YOU HEAR THAT A LOT, TOO.
AND WHY NOT?
THEY'VE HAD MORE THAN
A HALF-CENTURY TO GET IT RIGHT.
YOU START, YOU GOT
YOUR MEAT LAID OUT HERE.
YOU BASICALLY START SEASONING.
PUT YOUR RUB ON IT, WHICH IS
NO MORE THAN SALT AND PEPPER.
YOU HEARD HIM--
SALT, LOTS OF PEPPER,
FLAVOR FROM THE OAK FIRE
AND NOTHING ELSE.
A LITTLE SALT
MIXED IN THERE.
THIS BOWL'S DONE TIME,
HASN'T IT?
YES, IT HAS.
GET IN THERE.
OKAY.
I MEAN, DO I PUSH IT?
NO, NO, YOU JUST KINDA
SPREAD IT LIKE THAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
OKAY.
PUSH AS YOU'RE
SPREADING AROUND.
FEEL LIKE I'M AT MASSAGE SCHOOL
OR SOMETHING.
OKAY. YOU EVER THINK THAT,
YOU KNOW, YOU COULD PUT
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER IN THIS? NO?
I WOULDN'T CHANGE A THING,
YOU KNOW?
BOBBY'S BEEN DOIN' IT
LIKE THIS FOR 50 YEARS.
THAT'S THE WHOLE IDEA.
THAT'S WHY EVERYBODY STILL,
YOU KNOW,
KEEPS COMING BACK.
IT'S THE SAME EVERY TIME.
SO IF IT AIN'T BROKE,
DON'T FIX IT?
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
IT GOES ON IN THE MORNING
AT 4:30,
AND THAT'S
THE 1-SHOT DEAL.
(Bobby) YES.
WE KEEP ADDING IN BEHIND IT,
BUT WE'LL HAVE THE LAST MEAT
ON BY 10:00 IN THE MORNING.
SO JUST TOSS THAT
RIGHT UP THERE.
YOU GOT IT, PERFECT.
YOU GOTTA GET
IN THERE, GUY.
SO THERE'S
A WHOLE TECHNIQUE OF--
OF PLACEMENT, YEAH.
NO, OF KEEPING YOUR EYES CLOSED
AND YOUR MOUTH SHUT
WHEN YOU GET IN THERE, BECAUSE
I JUST TOOK, LIKE, FOUR HITS.
THERE'S A TECHNIQUE TO TELLING
WHEN IT'S DONE, TOO.
BEFORE THEY'RE READY TO PULL
OFF, THEY'RE REALLY TIGHTER.
AND THAT ONE'S READY
TO COME OFF.
HAVE YOU EVER FALLEN IN?
NO.
HAS LANCE EVER COME BY
AND JUST GIVEN YOU
A LITTLE NUDGE AND SAY,
"I WANT TO TAKE OVER TOMORROW"?
(laughs)
NO? LANCE,
I'M TELLING YOU...
I THINK--
YOU'RE THIS FAR AWAY
FROM OWNERSHIP, BABY.
IT GETS QUIET IN HERE
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE.
WHEN I'M BENT OVER HERE--
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY'LL DO ABOUT 40 BRISKETS
ON A BUSY DAY,
SLICIN' TILL THEY'RE GONE.
WHAT HAPPENS? I MEAN,
IS THERE A FULL PROTEST
WHEN YOU RUN OUT OF BRISKET?
YEAH, THEY GET UPSET
SOMETIMES, YOU KNOW?
WHAT DO YOU DO--
"I DROVE FROM HERE."
OR "I CAME THE OTHER DAY
AND Y'ALL WERE OUT,"
OR WHATEVER.
YOUR RESPONSE IS, "YOU
SHOULD'VE GOT HERE EARLIER"?
EXACTLY.
WHAT CAN WE GET
YOU, BUDDY?
WHAT DO YOU SERVE
ON A PORTION?
OH, WHATEVER THEY ORDER.
WE DON'T HAVE A SET PLATE
FOR ANYBODY.
EVERYBODY GETS WHAT--
THEY COME UP TO THE COUNTER
AND JUST CALL IT
TWO OR THREE SLICES. SIR?
TWO SLICES OF BRISKET.
LEAN OR MOIST?
SEE, HE ORDERED HIS BRISKET
WET--THAT MEANS HE WANTS
THE BACK END, THE MOIST,
WITH A LITTLE FAT ON IT.
THEY'LL ORDER IT WET,
MOIST, JUICY, FATTY.
YOU KNOW, THEY'VE ALL
KINDA GOT THEIR--
THEIR OWN LITTLE LINGO.
THE BRISKET'S ALWAYS BEEN
A TOP-SELLER,
BUT LOTS OF FOLKS COME IN
FOR THE SAUSAGES, TOO.
THAT'S GREAT.
HOW MANY LINKS WE GONNA GO
THROUGH AT LUNCH?
HOPEFULLY 150.
150 LINKS AT LUNCH.
YOU MAKE THREE KINDS
OF SAUSAGE, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
YOU MAKE THE REGULAR,
THE SUPER-HOT AND THE...
JALAPEÑO AND CHIPOTLE.
THE JALAPEÑO
AND THEN THE CHIPOTLE.
I WAS THINKING
THERE MIGHT BE SOMETHING
LIKE A CHICKEN SUN-DRIED TOMATO
COMING OUT OF HERE.
NOT YET.
SO DO YOU THINK
YOU'LL EVER STOP WORKING?
OH, I RETIRED TWO YEARS AGO
WHEN I CHANGED--TURNED 65.
YOU RETIRED?
I RETIRED.
OKAY, SO WHAT
IS THIS CALLED NOW?
WORKING.
OF COURSE, IT'S
MORE THAN JUST WORKING.
WHEN YOU WATCH BOBBY
TAKING CARE OF BUSINESS,
YOU CAN'T HELP
BUT BE IMPRESSED
THAT A GUY WHO'S BEEN
DOING IT ALL THESE YEARS
STILL REFUSES TO PHONE IT IN.
SOME OTHER FOLKS
HAVE NOTICED IT, TOO.
IN 2006, Y'ALL GOT
A JAMES BEARD AWARD?
IT'S SHOCKING, YOU KNOW? IT CAN
REALLY CATCH YOU BY SURPRISE.
WHAT WOULD YOUR DAD
HAVE THOUGHT OF THAT?
HE'D HAVE BEEN FLABBERGASTED
LIKE THE REST OF US. YEAH.
NOT THAT IT TAKES AN AWARD
TO TELL THESE FOLKS
WHAT THEY'VE KNOWN FOR YEARS.
IT'S GREAT, THE BEST.
BEST SAUSAGE AROUND.
JUST FANTASTIC.
DO YOU RECOGNIZE YOURSELF
IN BEING
THAT MUCH OF AN ICON
OF BARBECUE?
UH, NOT REALLY.
I MEAN, I'LL CONSIDER IT,
YOU KNOW,
JUST A--
JUST ANOTHER BARBECUER.
YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
MAKES THIS SO GOOD?
THE SMOKING.
THE SMOKING OF IT.
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE THE WOOD COMES FROM?
OFF THE TREES, RIGHT?
TREES.
NEXT STOP--
CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA...
MAY I HAVE YOUR ORDER?
WHERE THE BARBECUE
COMES TO YOUR CAR.
HOW'S IT GOING, BOSS?
AND YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT
THEY'RE DOING TO FRIED CHICKEN.
DUDE, THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS
RIGHT THERE.
I USED TO VISIT NORTH CAROLINA
A LOT WHEN I WAS A KID.
YOU SEE, THAT'S WHERE
MY GRANDMA MAMEE USED TO LIVE,
AND THAT'S WHERE I GOT
MY LOVE OF GRITS.
BUT HAD I KNOWN
ABOUT THE BAR-B-Q KING,
I THINK I WOULD HAVE VISITED
A LOT MORE OFTEN.
'CAUSE WHEN YOU PULL IN HERE,
YOU'RE HEADED
FOR SOME KILLER CAROLINA-STYLE,
VINEGAR-SAUCE-BASED BARBECUE...
GREAT.
WONDERFUL.
AT A DRIVE IN...
I'M GONNA DROP IT.
A CHARLOTTE LANDMARK
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOING IT
FOR NEARLY 50 YEARS.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
LIKE THIS.
LIKE THIS?
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
LIKE THIS.
THEY'VE BEEN DISHING UP
EVERYTHING FROM PULLED PORK
TO SLICED PORK,
FRIED CHICKEN DRENCHED IN THEIR
SECRET-RECIPE BARBECUE SAUCE...
LOOK AT HOW BEAUTIFUL--
EVEN HOMEMADE HUSH PUPPIES...
MMM.
ALL OF IT BROUGHT
TO YOUR CAR.
IN THE WORLD OF DRIVE-INS,
HOW DOES THIS RATE?
THIS IS TEN RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS TEN? THIS IS IT?
WHEN YOU COME TO CHARLOTTE,
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME.
AND IT'S A FAMILY JOINT,
RUN BY THE SAME FAMILY
SINCE 1959...
THIS IS THIRD GENERATION.
MAY I HAVE YOUR ORDER?
(raspy voice)
CAN I GET SOME...
WITH THE SAME GIZMOS,
THE SAME CARHOP SERVICE...
HEY, THERE,
YOU'RE SPILLING.
UH-OH.
THEY'VE HAD
SINCE THE VERY BEGINNING,
AND ONE OTHER THING...
TAKE IT.
THE SAME FOOD, MADE
THE SAME WAY--FROM SCRATCH.
WE MAKE EVERYTHING
ON PREMISES.
GUS, DID UNCLE PETE
TRAIN YOU HOW TO DO THIS?
YES, HE DID.
UNCLE PETE STARTED
RUNNING THIS PLACE
AND SMOKING THE SIGNATURE
PORK SHOULDERS IN '59.
HE RETIRED IN 2003,
BUT NO ONE'S SURE
WHAT THAT MEANS.
THERE YOU GO.
HE STILL SHOWS UP
ALMOST EVERY DAY.
LET ME ASK YOU SOMETHING--
UNCLE PETE'S NOT AROUND
RIGHT NOW.
ARE YOU THE BAR-B-Q KING,
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY?
NA, HE IS.
HE IS.
HE RETIRED, SO ME
AND MY BROTHER GEORGE
AND MY OTHER UNCLE STEVE
BOUGHT THE PLACE FROM PETE.
AND THERE'S STEVE'S WIFE MARIA,
GUS'S NIECE AMANDA...
MAY I HAVE YOUR ORDER?
AND WITH OR WITHOUT THE TITLE,
GUS IS NOW IN CHARGE
OF ALL THINGS BARBECUE,
LIKE PUTTING ON
THE PORK SHOULDER
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
THEY COOK
FOR SEVEN HOURS.
ACTUALLY, I'LL PUT
THE SMOKE ON AT SEVEN
AND CUT IT OFF
30 MINUTES LATER.
SO YOU LET IT START SMOKING
AT THE END.
LET'S SEE
THE END PRODUCT. WOW.
COOKED SO TENDER,
IT JUST ABOUT FALLS APART.
SEE HOW THE MEAT IS
JUST PULLING RIGHT OFF OF THERE.
HE'S LIKE A SURGEON
WITHOUT A KNIFE. YOU SEE THAT?
HOW MANY SHOULDERS
ARE WE GONNA USE?
THIS MACHINE WILL HOLD
22 SHOULDERS.
ABOUT 100 POUNDS.
EVERY DAY.
MOST ARE CHOPPED PORK,
SANDWICHES AND PLATTERS,
A LOT FOR SLICED PORK,
BUT THERE'S STILL
ONE MORE STEP.
THE ONLY SEASONING
THAT WE HAVE HERE
IS THE NATURAL SEASONING
OF THE PORK SHOULDER...
CORRECT.
THE SKIN, THE FAT AND THE BONE,
ALONG WITH THE HICKORY.
SO IF YOU'RE
NOT GONNA SEASON IT,
THEN YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO HAVE SOME DYNAMITE SAUCE
TO GO WITH IT.
I MAKE THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
AND YOU DO THE SHOULDER.
YES, SIR.
AM I GONNA BE HAPPY
WITH THIS?
I THINK SO.
OKAY.
OH, MAN.
GOOD?
MMM. SEE, I LOVE--
I LOVE THAT TANG
OF THAT VINEGAR
AND THE SOFT PORK--
NICE COMPLEMENT.
YOU'RE RIGHT, MAN.
IF YOU HAD TOO MUCH
SEASONING ON THAT--
I MEAN,
THAT SAUCE IS WOW!
NOW HOW OFTEN DO YOU
MAKE THE SAUCE?
YOU GO AHEAD.
I'LL FOLLOW YOU.
SAUCE--WE MAKE IT
EVERY DAY.
EVERY SINGLE DAY
YOU MAKE SAUCE?
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
THIS MUCH SAUCE?
YES, WE DO.
I THINK THEY DRINK IT.
THIS IS THE MAIN INGREDIENT
IN THE BARBECUE SAUCE?
VINEGAR, SUGAR?
BROWN SUGAR.
TOMATO?
TOMATO-BASED.
HEY, HEY, WHAT'S THIS?
THIS IS, UH, A PART
OF THAT SOMETHIN'-SOMETHIN'
I WAS TELLIN' YOU ABOUT.
CAN I TASTE IT?
SURE.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
ON THE MILD SIDE.
(chuckles)
WHAT IS THAT?
IT TASTES LIKE TABASCO,
WORCESTERSHIRE AND LIQUID SMOKE.
IT'S A FAMILY SECRET,
AND SO IS THE SPICE MIX.
THIS IS MORE
SOMETHIN'-SOMETHIN'?
YOU TAKE THE SPICE MIX--
HERE, I'LL STIR.
YOU WANT TO STIR.
DO WE SING A SONG
OR ANYTHING?
GO FOR IT.
I'M SINGING IT RIGHT NOW
IN MY HEAD.
OKAY.
THEY FINISH WITH LEMONS
AND COOK FOR THREE HOURS.
THE RECIPE HASN'T CHANGED
IN ALMOST 50 YEARS.
THEY'VE BEEN DOIN' IT
FOR SO LONG,
THEY JUST GOT IT DOWN
TO A FINE ART.
AND THIS MIGHT JUST BE
THEIR MASTERPIECE.
OH, MAN.
WHEN WE COME BACK--
BARBECUE CHICKEN
LIKE I'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
YOU WERE BLESSED
WITH THE BARBECUE CHICKEN LOVE
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
FOR SPECIAL TODAY?
WE'RE AT THE BAR-B-Q KING
IN CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA,
WHERE THE PULLED PORK'S
THE BOMB.
AND WAIT TILL THEY LIGHT
THE FUSE ON THEIR CHICKEN.
SO THIS GOT BREADED--IT'S
JUST GETTIN' BREADED ALL DAY?
IT JUST GOT BREADED.
DIFFERENT COOKING TIMES
FOR THE LEGS, THE THIGHS,
THE WINGS, THE BREASTS?
EXACTLY.
SO THIS IS ALL DONE
RIGHT NOW.
THIS IS ALL DONE
WANT TO BARBECUE IT UP?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
BARBECUE IT UP?
THIS IS HOW WE'RE GONNA
BARBECUE OUR CHICKEN TODAY.
WE'RE GONNA BARBECUE
THE FRIED CHICKEN?
THE FRIED CHICKEN.
THIS IS
AN ORIGINAL RECIPE HERE.
THE DIFFERENT PART IS--
YOU FRIED IT CRISPY-CRISPY.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA
SUBMERGE IT.
SO THIS IS KINDA LIKE
A CROSS BETWEEN...
FRIED CHICKEN,
BARBECUE CHICKEN
AND BUFFALO WINGS.
AND BUFFALO WINGS,
EXACTLY.
OH, MAN.
I DON'T GET SURPRISED
VERY OFTEN, I MEAN REALLY,
BUT I GOTTA TELL YA...
GOOD?
DUDE, THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS
RIGHT THERE.
DUDE, YOU WERE BLESSED
WITH THE BARBECUE CHICKEN LOVE
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
THAT IS FUNKY AND DELICIOUS.
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED TO HAVE
ANYTHING ELSE ON THE MENU.
BUT THEY DO--
ALMOST THE EXACT SAME MENU
THEY'VE HAD
SINCE THE VERY BEGINNING.
SINCE 1959, THERE'S LIKE,
MAYBE TWO OR THREE ITEMS
THAT WE'VE ADDED.
(woman over intercom)
MAY I HAVE YOUR ORDER?
(Guy) EVEN THE ORDERING SYSTEM
HAS STAYED THE SAME.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, YOU WRITE
THE STATION DOWN ON THE TOP.
THE STATION, OKAY.
YEAH, AND THEN YOU
FLIP IT UP.
OKAY.
YOU HOLD THIS DOWN AND YOU SAY,
"MAY I HAVE YOUR ORDER?"
(woman over intercom)
BARBECUE CHICKEN.
LIKE, THAT SAYS "MYNOM."
IT SAYS
MAYONNAISE, NO MUSTARD."
TO YOU IT DOES.
TO REGULAR PEOPLE
IT SAYS "MYNOM."
YEAH.
AND THEN YOU
SEND IT DOWN.
NO, YOU HAVE TO WALK.
UH, ONE BARBECUE...
(Guy) THE 50-YEAR-OLD
DELIVERY SYSTEM...
WHERE'S 38?
COME ON.
OH, IT'S A SNAP.
(Guy) REMEMBER,
I'M NEW AT THIS.
I NEED BREAD FOR TWO.
THERE YOU GO, BOSS,
BREAD FOR TWO.
GOT THAT?
(Amanda) YOU QUITTIN'?
OH, I'M DONE.
I ONLY MADE IT
THROUGH FIVE ORDERS.
BUT I THINK
THEY'LL DO OKAY WITHOUT ME,
'CAUSE IN CHARLOTTE,
THIS PLACE IS KING.
FABULOUS.
CHOPPED AND SLICE,
FRIED AND DIPPED,
THEY'RE STILL MAKIN' IT
FROM SCRATCH.
WE GOT A GOOD THING
GOIN' HERE--
A GOOD OPERATION,
GOOD PEOPLE,
GOOD FOOD, HARD WORKERS
AND HAS BEEN
IN BUSINESS FOR 50 YEARS.
SO WHY WOULD WE EVER CHANGE?
I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE
FOR YEARS.
REALLY?
THIS IS A HOT SPOT HERE.
THIS IS. HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
THE CHICKEN--
THE FRIED CHICKEN
THAT THEY DIP?
TELL ME THAT'S
NOT OUT OF BOUNDS, HUH?
IT IS OFF THE HOOK.
HEY, I KNOW A GUY
THAT SAYS THAT A LOT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO CHASE DOWN.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
OKAY, YOU READY?
(Andrea) I'M READY.
I DIDN'T EVEN PUSH
A BUTTON YET.
HOW'D YOU KNOW I WAS READY?
BECAUSE I HEARD YOU.