HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI.
WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP,
IT'S JUST LIKE YESTERDAY...
THERE YOU ARE, HONEY.
AT A 50-YEAR-OLD DINER
NEAR BOSTON,
WHERE EVERYTHING'S A CLASSIC...
NOTHING BETTER
THAN GOOD OLD DINER FOOD.
EVEN THE ATTITUDE.
GET HIM SOME MORE COFFEE.
YOU GOT IT IN YOUR HAND.
A TINY JOINT IN NEW JERSEY...
EXCUSE ME.
NOT MUCH ROOM HERE.
SERVING BIG GUYS
BIG FOOD,
MADE LIKE YOU'D NEVER EXPECT
IN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
WHO BONED, ROLLED
AND TIED THIS?
I DID IT MYSELF.
AND A LANDMARK
IN SOUTH CAROLINA,
WHERE THEY'RE PILING IN
FOR PILES OF ONION RINGS
ON TOP OF JUST
ABOUT ANYTHING...
AND WAIT TILL YOU SEE
HOW YOUR ORDER GOES IN.
DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER
WITH MUSTARD!
THERE YOU GO!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
IT'S PRETTY AMAZING,
BUT ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
PLACES LIKE THIS,
LIKE KELLY'S DINER HERE
IN SOMERVILLE, MASS,
ARE BOOMING AGAIN.
50 TO 60 YEARS AFTER SERVING
THEIR VERY FIRST MEALS,
THE ALL-AMERICAN CLASSICS
ARE AS POPULAR AS EVER
OR EVEN MORE SO.
IT'S GREAT...
AND EXACTLY WHAT DINERS
WERE BORN TO BE...
THERE YOU ARE, HONEY.
A PLACE WHERE YOU
JUST WANT TO HANG OUT...
IT'S NICE PEOPLE,
GREAT ATMOSPHERE.
HERE WE GO.
WITH THAT CLASSIC
WAITRESS ATTITUDE.
FEEL LIKE A SECRETARY. YOU CAN
SAY MOST ANYTHING TO CUSTOMERS,
'CAUSE THEY COME IN HERE
EXPECTING THAT.
OH, YOU GOT
DECISIONS ALREADY.
AND OH, YEAH,
ONE OTHER THING...
NOTHING BETTER
THAN GOOD OLD DINER FOOD.
HOMEMADE FAVORITES
THAT WON'T BREAK THE BANK.
THEY CALL IT COMFORT FOOD
IF MAKES YOU COMFORTABLE.
FOR JAY HOLMES, IT'S
THE PERFECT CHILDHOOD MEMORY.
DANNY BOY, PASS ME
A COUPLE EGGS.
AS A KID, HE AND HIS DAD
WERE DINER-OBSESSED.
I MADE A PEPPERIDGE FARM
COOKIE ROOF.
AND HE'D GET ME UP
EARLY IN THE MORNING.
WE'D GO--WHEN IT
CAME TO LUNCHTIME,
WE'D ALWAYS FIND
A DIFFERENT DINER TO GO TO.
AND WE KIND OF USED
TO, LIKE, YOU KNOW,
TALK ABOUT HOW COOL DINERS ARE
AND THIS AND THAT.
IT WOULD BE GREAT
TO OWN A DINER SOMEDAY.
SO WHEN THIS PLACE
BECAME AVAILABLE,
HE AND HIS DAD WENT
TO TAKE A LOOK.
BY THEN, IT WASN'T
EVEN A RESTAURANT ANYMORE.
...THAT THIS WAS A DINER
IN NEW CASTLE, DELAWARE,
AND IT WAS ACTUALLY A NURSERY--
TREES, PLANTS, SHRUBS...
WERE IN THE DINER?
EVERYWHERE. YOU COULDN'T
EVEN SEE THE DINER.
AND WE'RE LOOKIN' AROUND
WITH ALL THE PLANTS.
I SAID TO MY FATHER,
I SAID, "JEEZ."
BUT HE HAS A REAL
GOOD IMAGINATION.
HE SAID, "IT LOOKED GOOD,"
AND THEN I LOOKED AT THIS.
I GO, "AT LEAST
THE WALK-IN'S STILL HERE."
SO THEY SHIPPED IT
TO SOMERVILLE, RESTORED IT
AND TEN YEARS LATER, IT SEEMS
LIKE IT'S BEEN HERE FOREVER.
BUT THIS IS CLASSIC.
AND NOT JUST THE LOOK--
THE FOOD'S CLASSIC, TOO.
OH, IT'S AWESOME.
(Jay) HOMEMADE COOKIN',
COOKIN' IT FROM SCRATCH,
FRESH INGREDIENTS.
EVERYTHING'S GOTTA BE FRESH.
A REGULAR CHEESE OMELET.
(Guy) HOW MANY EGGS ARE
WE GONNA GO THROUGH TODAY?
150 DOZEN.
150 DOZEN EGGS?
YEAH.
WHY NOT? JAY'S GOT EGGS
ANY WAY YOU WANT 'EM,
EVEN A CRABMEAT EGGS BENEDICT
AND ALL THE OTHER DINER BASICS,
JUST DONE HIS WAY,
LIKE CORNED BEEF HASH,
THE WAY HIS GRANDFATHER DID IT.
HE HAD A GREAT RECIPE
FOR CORNED BEEF HASH.
HE SHOWED US HOW TO DO IT THIS
WAY, AND WE NEVER TURNED BACK.
EVERYBODY LOVED IT.
JUST GRIND EVERYTHING UP.
WHAT YOU GONNA DO?
BUY IT IN THE CAN?
THAT'S THE WORST.
AND GET THIS--
THEN HE BAKES IT.
HE SAYS THAT ADDS FLAVOR
AND CRISPINESS...
LOOKS GOOD.
BEFORE THE HASH
IS FINISHED ON THE GRILL.
OH, I LOVE IT.
OH, IT'S THE BOMB.
I JUST HAD SOME.
WHEN YOU'RE TAUGHT
A CERTAIN WAY,
YOU DON'T KNOW
ANY OTHER WAY.
STILL, JAY'S NOT SHY
ABOUT INVENTING NEW TWISTS FOR
OLD FAVORITES, LIKE MEAT LOAF.
AND I TOP IT OFF
WITH, LIKE, AN ALFREDO--
A HOMEMADE ALFREDO SAUCE WITH--
HAS MUSHROOMS IN IT.
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM?
I MADE IT UP.
SO NOT ONLY ARE
YOU OWNER OF A DINER.
NOW YOU'RE TURNING
INTO A CHEF. I LIKE IT.
OH, YEAH--BIG-TIME.
BIG-TIME CHEF.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF OIL?
HEAT UP THE OIL--
MUSHROOMS, ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC. LET THAT BROWN.
ADD THE HEAVY CREAM.
OKAY.
PUT A LITTLE BASIL.
THEN WHEN DO WE ADD
THE PARMESAN CHEESE?
AFTER IT STARTS TO REDUCE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE WHISK.
THIS IS, LIKE, SOME
GOURMET MEAT LOAF, DUDE.
OH, YEAH.
NOW I'M JUST GONNA PUT THIS
OVER THE TOP OF THE MEAT LOAF.
OH, I IMAGINE THAT'S NOT
GONNA TASTE JUST INCREDIBLE.
IT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND JUST COOK IT
RIGHT IN THERE?
COVER IT UP, BAKE IT IN THE OVEN
FOR 45 MINUTES OR SO.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR THAT
IN ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
SO WILL THE CROWD.
HI. MORE COFFEE?
BY NOW, JAY KNOWS EXACTLY
WHAT THE LOCALS WANT...
IT'S MY FAVORITE KIND
OF CHICKEN POT PIE.
FAVORITES LIKE
PORTUGUESE LINGUICA SAUSAGE
AND EVEN FRESH
NEW ENGLAND LOBSTER ROLL.
MY FISH GUY JOE--HE'LL CALL ME
UP AND GIVE ME A GOOD DEAL.
MY FISH GUY JOE?
YEP--FISH GUY JOE.
(Guy) NOT EVERYBODY
HAS A FISH GUY JOE.
HOW ABOUT THEM RED SOX?
HE'LL CALL ME UP,
AND HE'LL GIVE ME A DEAL.
HE'LL SAY, "OH, I GOT
A GREAT DEAL ON CULLS,"
WHICH ARE 1-CLAW LOBSTERS.
1-CLAW LOBSTERS?
YEP. COOK 'EM UP.
AND THAT'S BECAUSE
THEY'RE GROWN WITH ONE CLAW,
OR BECAUSE...
I THINK IT'S--LEGEND HAS IT,
THEY GOT INTO A FIGHT
AND LOST A CLAW OR WHATEVER.
LEGEND--THE LEGEND
OF THE 1-CLAWED LOBSTER.
WHATEVER THE LEGEND,
JAY CAN GET
THESE 1-CLAWED CULLS CHEAPER...
THIS IS A GOOD-SIZED ONE
RIGHT THERE. LOOK AT THAT.
WHICH MAKES 'EM GREAT
FOR A DINER MENU.
MIX IT UP WITH MAYONNAISE,
CELERY SALT, CELERY.
NOW WHERE DID
THIS RECIPE COME FROM?
RIGHT UP HERE. IT'S ALL UP HERE.
CHOP UP ALL THE MEAT.
YOU WANT TO LEAVE BIG CHUNKS,
BIG CHUNKS.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S GOOD.
THERE WE GO.
A LITTLE CELERY SALT--
RIGHT THERE BEHIND YOU.
LITTLE SHAKE?
YEP.
THAT ENOUGH?
THAT'S ENOUGH, YEP.
OKAY. HOW MUCH MAYONNAISE
DO WE USE?
AS LITTLE AS YOU CAN--
JUST TO COVER THE LOBSTER
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU DON'T WANT TO PUT
TOO MUCH MAYONNAISE.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S HOW WE MIX IT?
I'LL BET YOU THAT'S GOOD.
I SHOULD TRY IT,
DON'T YOU THINK?
YEAH, TRY SOME.
YOU'VE BEEN DYING
TO TRY IT.
I LIKE HOW YOU PUT JUST A LITTLE
BIT OF MAYONNAISE IN THERE.
IT DOESN'T MASK ALL THE FLAVOR
OF ALL THE LOBSTER.
IT REALLY COMES OUT.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF, MAN.
RIGHT OFF THE BOAT--
FRESH AS CAN BE.
JAY ONLY DOES THE LOBSTER
ON OCCASION
WHEN HE CAN GET
THE FIRE SALE ON 1-CLAWS,
'CAUSE HE INSISTS
KEEPING PRICES DOWN
IS A BIG PART OF BEING
A REAL NEIGHBORHOOD DINER.
AS A BROKE COLLEGE STUDENT,
I ENJOY IT VERY MUCH.
AND THIS REALLY IS
THE NEIGHBORHOOD PLACE.
OH, THE COPS ALWAYS KNOW WHERE
THE GOOD FOOD IS? DEFINITELY.
I WOULDN'T
EAT ANYWHERE ELSE,
ONLY KELLY'S FOR BREAKFAST
AND LUNCH.
NO, NOT DINNER.
THEY CLOSE AT 3:00.
GUYS, HOW WE DOING?
I GOT A DECAF.
TILL THEN, THIS PLACE
IS FULL OF REGULARS,
WHO COME IN SO OFTEN,
THE WAITRESSES ACTUALLY
KNOW WHAT THEY WANT.
ONE A COFFEE, ONE A TEA,
NO ONIONS--THEY ALREADY KNOW.
THERE YOU GO.
AND THAT'S ONLY PART
OF THE CLASSIC WAITRESS
FLOOR SHOW HERE.
AND HOT SAUCE.
ONE PART SPEED...
YOU HAVE TO HAVE,
LIKE, TRACK SHOES ON.
YOU WANT
SOME MORE COFFEE?
ONE PART ATTITUDE.
GIVE HIM SOME MORE COFFEE.
YOU GOT IT IN YOUR HAND.
I GOT NOTHING ELSE TO DO
BUT LET HIM DO MY WORK.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
I HAVE TO GET
SWEET'N LOW.
YOU JUST BRING IT OVER IN HAND?
WE DON'T WANT TO PUT 'EM IN--
YEP. NOTHING FANCY HERE.
TAKE THE JUICE
OVER HERE TO GRANDMA?
THE SCREWDRIVER.
OH, THANK YOU.
THERE YOU GO!
AND WHEN YOU'RE IN THE MIDDLE
OF ALL THIS,
IT'S EASY TO FORGET THIS PLACE
HASN'T BEEN HERE FOREVER.
IT'S LIKE A LOST
WAY OF LIFE.
KELLY'S DINER IN SOMERVILLE
REALLY IS A REBORN CLASSIC,
EVERYTHING A DINER WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE YEARS AGO,
A PLACE TO HANG,
TO EAT A GREAT MEAL
AND TO MAKE SOME FRIENDS.
I APPRECIATE YOU LETTING ME
TRAIN UNDER YOUR TUTELAGE.
OH, HONEY,
IF I TRAINED YOU, WHOA!
NEXT, WE'RE HEADIN'
TO NEW JERSEY,
'CAUSE I WANT
TO SEE WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN A FIREMAN
WITH NO DINER EXPERIENCE
DECIDES TO RESTORE A CLASSIC.
SO WHEN I DO SOMETHING,
I TRY TO DO IT TO PERFECT.
WHEN IT COMES
TO CLASSIC AMERICAN ROAD FOOD,
NO PLACE DOES IT BIGGER
THAN NEW JERSEY.
I MEAN, THEY GOT MORE DINERS
THAN ANY OTHER STATE.
BUT COME CHECK
THIS ONE OUT WITH ME,
AND YOU'LL SEE WHY YOU DON'T
HAVE TO BE BIG TO BE BIG.
(Guy) HOW MANY SEATS DO
YOU HAVE IN THIS DINER?
INSIDE THE DINER,
WE HAVE NINE STOOLS.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
DO YOU SERVE IN A DAY?
250 PEOPLE.
WHERE WE GOING?
RIGHT THERE.
AT MIKE GIUNTA'S TINY BAY WAY
DINER IN LINDEN, NEW JERSEY...
EXCUSE ME.
NOT MUCH ROOM HERE.
IT'S A ZOO.
SAUSAGE CHEESE OMELET.
OKAY, DID YOU GET THAT ORDER?
WHITE OR RYE?
WHITE.
WHITE?
WHITE. HOW CAN
WE LOSE COMMUNICATION?
WE'RE ONLY 4 FEET APART!
THEY'RE SERVING
BIG PLATES...
CORNED BEEF HASH.
BIG CROWDS...
GET OVER HERE, MAN!
MMM!
AND BIG GUYS.
WHAT DO YOU
NEED, BUDDY?
I NEED FOOD.
THE DINER SITS
JUST ACROSS THE STREET
FROM ONE OF THE COUNTRY'S
BIGGEST REFINERIES...
YOU WORKED THERE
A LONG TIME?
20 YEARS.
AND A FEW MILES
FROM THE PORT OF NEWARK.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE HERE FOR.
YOU KNOW, GRAB AN EGG
AND A BACON SANDWICH
AND A COFFEE AND GO TO WORK.
GOOD?
YO.
ANYBODY WANT A MOCHACCINO?
THERE AIN'T
NO MOCHACCINO HERE.
NO?
I'M STICKIN' TO MY DIET.
EVEN THE WHOLE FAMILY'S THERE--
THE FATHER AND THE TWO SONS.
LOOK AT 'EM.
NOW WHAT DO
YOU GUYS DO?
TRUCK DRIVERS.
TRUCKS--TRACTOR-TRAILER.
WELL, YOU ALMOST HAD THAT,
YOU KNOW, TOGETHER.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT?
A SAUSAGE, EGG
AND CHEESE HERE.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
I THINK IT'S THE LOVE
THAT MY FRIEND PUTS
IN THE FOOD HERE.
THE LOVE.
YES.
YOU CAN TASTE THE LOVE?
WHEN YOU COME IN HERE, IT TASTES
LIKE FOOD STRAIGHT FROM HOME.
I SWEAR.
YOUR MOM COOKED THIS WAY?
NO. NO. IT'S BETTER
THAN MY MOM'S.
YOU GIVE THEM A GOOD SANDWICH
FOR A GOOD PRICE,
THEY'RE COMIN' BACK...
LIKE THE BAY WAY
MONSTER BURGER...
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY GOOD.
TWO 8-OUNCE PATTIES--
THAT'S A POUND OF BEEF--
TAYLOR HAM, LETTUCE, TOMATO.
THEY'LL EVEN ADD CHEESE
AND BACON IF YOU WANT.
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING ON IT
THAT I LIKE...
EXCEPT FOR TOMATO.
AH, WE DON'T EAT
ANY HEALTH FOOD HERE.
I GREW UP IN DINERS,
AND I NEED TO HAVE
EVERYTHING THE BEST.
BUT GET THIS...
SCRAMBLED EGG
ON WHITE TOAST, PLEASE.
(Mike) GOT IT.
BEFORE THE BAY WAY, MIKE
HAD NEVER RUN A DINER BEFORE...
LARGE OR SMALL COFFEE?
OR ANY KIND OF RESTAURANT.
(Mike) I'M A FIREMAN BY TRADE,
AND I OWN A GARBAGE BUSINESS
AROUND THE CORNER.
WE NEEDED A PLACE TO PUT UP
A GARAGE, SO WE FIGURED, "HEY.
"LET'S KNOCK THIS PLACE DOWN.
IT'S OLD, DIRTY, GRUNGY.
LET'S KNOCK IT DOWN
AND PUT UP A GARAGE."
WE DECIDED NOT
TO KNOCK IT DOWN, OKAY?
HOW DID THIS COME UP?
I MEAN, HOW DO YOU
DECIDE NOT TO KNOCK--
I'M GONNA KNOCK IT DOWN.
I'M NOT GONNA KNOCK IT DOWN.
I MEAN, YOU GUYS ARE SITTIN'
AROUND THE POOL AT THE HOUSE
AND YOU SAY...
NO, YOU KNOW WHAT?
THERE'S NOT THAT MANY
GOOD PLACES TO EAT AROUND HERE.
SO YOU BUILT YOUR
OWN DINER FOR YOURSELF?
THAT'S IT.
I LIKE IT.
BUT IT WASN'T EASY.
AFTER 50 YEARS,
THE PLACE WAS A MESS.
AND YOU SHUT IT DOWN BECAUSE
IT NEEDED TO BE TOTALLY...
TOTALLY REMODELED.
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU
TO REFURBISH IT?
2, 2 1/2 MONTHS.
TO GET FROM THIS...
TO THIS.
WE'RE IN NEW JERSEY.
IT'S GOTTA SCREAM, "DINER."
MAN, IS IT SCREAMIN'!
I THOUGHT IT WAS GREAT
BECAUSE THE ALTERNATIVE
WAS THAT HE WAS
GONNA TEAR IT DOWN.
THAT'S MY PASSION.
WHEN I DO SOMETHING,
I TRY TO DO IT TO PERFECT...
LIKE LEARNING THE BIZ
IN A MATTER OF MONTHS...
WHO'S NEXT?
ANYBODY NEXT? ANYBODY?
AND CRANKIN' OUT GOOD FOOD
THAT'S JUST AS FAST
AS FAST FOOD.
IS IT TO GO
OR FOR HERE?
80% IS TO GO.
BAY WAY DINER.
CHICKEN PHILLY.
WE DO HAVE SOUP TODAY.
OH, YOU GOT THE BAG?
(woman) YEAH,
I GOT MY BAG.
OH, I'M SORRY.
SHE'S GOT IT, MAN.
YEAH, THE GIRL'S
TAKIN' CARE OF US.
ARE THE CAMERAS ROLLIN'--
YOU GET INVOLVED? COME ON!
BUT IT'S THIS GUY WHO'S
REALLY DRAWING THE CROWDS.
JOE GONZALEZ
IS A SHORT ORDER COOK
WHO OUGHT TO BE CALLED
A SHORT ORDER CHEF.
THIS IS GOURMET OVER HERE.
OH, THIS IS--
I ONLY PICK THE BEST.
I MEAN, I THOUGHT--
NOW HOW DID YOU HIRE HIM?
AD IN THE PAPER.
AD IN THE PAPER?
OUT OF 42 CHEFS.
HE'S JUST TAKIN' ORDERS
LIKE THIS...
THAT'S IT.
AND HE'S SMILIN'
THE WHOLE TIME...
AND TURNING OUT FOOD
YOU'D HARDLY EXPECT TO FIND
AT A 9-SEAT DINER,
LIKE CAJUN-GRILLED CHICKEN,
MARINATED OVERNIGHT AND SERVED
OVER TRICOLORED PASTA.
AND THIS IS THE FAMOUS
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK?
THIS BRINGS ME BACK 45 YEARS AGO
WHEN I WAS A KID
EATING AT DINERS.
AND THIS IS A PHILLY MADE
COMPLETELY FROM SCRATCH...
JOE.
YES, SIR.
STARTIN' DOWN HERE
IN THE SUBMARINE.
JEEZ! IS THERE A HEIGHT
REQUIREMENT IN HERE?
THIS IS THE SPECIALTY
OF THE HOUSE,
'CAUSE THIS IS THE PHILLY
CHEESESTEAK, RIGHT?
THE PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
NOW WHAT SIZE TOP ROUND,
ABOUT A 20-POUNDER?
YEAH, JUST--ONE COME
IN THIS MORNING, 22 POUNDS.
WE USE A CHICKEN BASE.
SO CHICKEN BASE,
NOT CHICKEN STOCK?
NO. IT'S CHICKEN BASE.
SO WE RUB IT WITH THAT,
AND WE MARINATE IT OVERNIGHT?
EXACTLY.
THEN HE OVEN-ROASTS IT WITH
CELERY, ONIONS AND CARROTS
FOR 2 1/2 HOURS
AND THEN LETS IT COOL...
THE THINNEST YOU CAN.
BEFORE HE SLICES IT.
WHO BONED, ROLLED
AND TIED THIS?
I DID IT MYSELF.
BUT YOU CAN BUY IT
DONE THAT WAY.
WHY DO YOU DO IT YOURSELF?
WE LIKE TO DO IT FRESH.
AND IT SHOWS,
FROM TOP-ROUND CHEESESTEAKS...
DANNY, WHAT'S UP, MY MAN?
TO MAKING EVERY CUSTOMER
FEEL WELCOME,
THE BAY WAY'S WHAT A DINER
WAS BORN TO BE.
AND I'D RATHER BE HERE
THAN ONE OF THEM BIG,
KIND OF COMMERCIAL-TYPE THINGS.
LOOK AT THAT!
MIKE'S STILL A LITTLE STUNNED
TO BE RUNNING THE KIND OF PLACE
HE ALWAYS WANTED
TO HANG OUT IN AND SUCCEEDING.
THERE YOU GO, HUH?
HE SAYS YOU ALWAYS
KEEP THE WORKING GUYS
WELL FED AND HAPPY,
BUT EVERYONE'S WELCOME.
JUST PARK BEHIND THE BACKHOE
AND COME ON IN.
GET OVER HERE, MAN!
NEXT, WE'RE HEADED SOUTH TO
A PLACE WHERE THEY PACK 'EM IN
BY THE HUNDREDS,
MAKE MEALS IN SECONDS,
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOING IT
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY
FOR OVER 60 YEARS.
(man) HURRY BACK. YOU GOTTA
HURRY BACK HERE.
I'M COMIN! I'M COMIN!
FOR 60 YEARS, FOLKS AROUND
SPARTANBURG, SOUTH CAROLINA,
HAVE BEEN IN LOVE
WITH A LOCAL LANDMARK
CALLED THE BEACON DRIVE-IN,
AND FOR GOOD REASON.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
ANYBODY GOT THAT HAM?
THIS PLACE IS LOUD.
GRILLED PHILLY CHEESE
ON THIS LINE.
IT'S PACKED. IT'S BUSY.
PHILLY CHEESE A-PLENTY.
KEEP ON WALKIN'.
AND IT IS GOOD.
IT'S THE ULTIMATE INDULGENCE.
WE GIVE A LOT OF FOOD--
GOOD FOOD--
AT VERY REASONABLE PRICES.
CHEESEBURGER, FRIED HAM!
IT MAY LOOK LIKE PANDEMONIUM,
BUT I'M TELLING YOU.
THESE GUYS HAVE A PLAYBOOK.
WELL, LET'S GO. WE'RE GONNA
GET DOWN TO BUSINESS.
YOU GOTTA SUIT UP.
I GOTTA SUIT UP?
SUIT UP.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT THIS
OVER MY HEAD?
I AM. ALL RIGHT, TIE IT UP
AND LET'S GO.
OH, THIS ONE'S READY
TO GO NOW. OKAY.
THEY'VE GOT A SYSTEM
FOR CRANKIN' IT ALL OUT.
KEEP THE PROCESS ROLLING.
GOTTA KEEP 'EM GOING.
WRAP IT TWICE. IF IT'S COMIN'
LOOSE, WE WON'T LOSE IT.
THERE YOU GO.
WE WILL SEE--
IN A WEEK'S TIME,
WE'LL SEE 15,000
TO 20,000 CUSTOMERS.
BUT NOW WAIT A SECOND.
WE ONLY HAVE, LIKE,
40,000, 45,000 PEOPLE
THAT LIVE IN SPARTANBURG.
RIGHT.
SO WE HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
EAT WITH US A LOT.
WE GOT TOURIST GROUPS.
IT TASTES DELICIOUS.
MOST OF THE MEALS COME COVERED
IN A MOUNTAIN OF FRENCH FRIES
AND HOMEMADE ONION RINGS,
A COMBINATION
THEY CALL A-PLENTY.
CHILI CHEESE A-PLENTY.
THAT'S THE BEST SELLER--
A CHEESEBURGER TOPPED
WITH HOMEMADE CHILI,
SOMEWHERE UNDER ALL OF THIS.
IT COMES AS A DOUBLE, TOO,
OR WITH BACON
OR A BARBECUE A-PLENTY.
THEY'VE GOT PLENTY A-PLENTY...
GOT A HAM
AND CHEESE A-PLENTY.
AND AT THE HEART OF 'EM ALL--
FRESH, HOMEMADE ONION RINGS.
OKAY, KENNY.
I WANT THE RUNDOWN
ON THE FAMOUS RINGS A-PLENTY.
IT'S OUR SIGNATURE
PRODUCT, OKAY?
OKAY.
WE SELL OVER 2 TONS A WEEK,
AND THEY COME IN EVERY DAY.
WE SLICE 'EM. WE RING 'EM.
WE BATTER 'EM.
AND IN FACT, TODAY, WE'VE
GOT 1,000 POUNDS OF ONIONS
TO PREPARE JUST FOR TODAY.
1,000 POUNDS OF ONIONS?
1,000 POUNDS.
FOR 1 DAY?
1 DAY. TOMORROW,
WE USE ANOTHER 1,000.
(whistles)
THAT'S A LOT, MAN.
IT'S LIKE I'M MINING
FOR GOLD OR SOMETHING.
THAT IS GOLD.
THAT IS GOLD!
I CAN START
PUTTIN' 'EM OVER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, THAT'S IT?
THAT'S READY NOW.
GAME OVER.
NOW I TAKE THIS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WALK ON OVER.
YOU USE YOUR STOMACH
RIGHT THERE, PRESS IT UP
AND THEN TOSS HIGH
TILL THEY SPLATTER, OKAY?
OKAY.
LET'S SEE HOW YOU DO 'EM.
THIS AIN'T YOUR FIRST RODEO,
IS IT, KENNY?
NO.
OKAY.
IT'S HOT OVER HERE!
IT IS HOT.
ALL RIGHT, YOU
SEE 'EM A-FLOATIN'?
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY.
HANG IT UP ON THE RACK.
AND WHAT?
YOU'RE GONNA DUMP IT IN.
INTO HERE?
YEAH. LET ME
SHOW YOU THIS.
OKAY.
OKAY, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO REACH OVER.
(man laughing)
OH, I KNOW WHY
YOU GUYS ARE LAUGHIN'!
DO YOU GUYS KNOW
ABOUT TONGS?
WE DON'T USE--
YOU AIN'T GOT
NO TIME, RIGHT?
NOW ALL THE CRAZINESS HERE
IS THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
FROM THE VERY BEGINNING.
THIS IS THE MAN
THAT STARTED THE BEACON,
AND THAT IS MR. WHITE.
AND HE STARTED
THE RESTAURANT IN 1946,
SOLD IT TO US IN 1998.
AND ALL THOSE PILES OF FOOD--
THOSE WERE HIS IDEA.
AND IT WAS RIGHT
AFTER THE DEPRESSION
WHEN PEOPLE
DIDN'T EAT GOOD.
RIGHT.
SO ONE OF THE THINGS HE
STARTED THE RESTAURANT OUT ON
WAS SERVING GOOD FOOD
AT CHEAP PRICES
AND GIVING PEOPLE
A LOT OF IT.
THERE WAS ANOTHER COMPANY
FROM CALIFORNIA
THAT WAS INTERESTED
IN BUYING IT,
AND ONE OF THE REASONS
THAT WE ENDED UP GETTING IT
WAS THAT THEY KNEW THAT WE
WOULD KEEP IT AND RUN IT LIKE--
'CAUSE YOU KNOW THOSE CALIFORNIA
GUYS WOULD GET IN HERE.
THEY'D BE SERVING SUSHI,
NEXT THING YOU KNOW.
AND THAT WON'T GO HERE.
WHAT WILL GO HERE
IS WHAT'S GONE FOR YEARS...
WHO HAD A CHILI CHEESE
WITH BACON?
NOT JUST THE A-PLENTIES,
BUT HUGE SERVINGS OF ALL KINDS
OF DOWN-HOME COOKIN'.
WE GOT CHILI BURGERS,
PLAIN HAMBURGERS, HAMBURGERS,
BEACON BURGERS.
THIS IS CALLED
THE HASH, RIGHT?
THAT'S CORRECT, YES.
NOW THE HASH
IS NOT THE TYPICAL HASH,
LIKE CORNED BEEF HASH?
RIGHT.
BUT IT'S THE SHOULDER?
YES.
SO IT'S THE BEEF SHOULDER,
PULLED PORK, OKAY?
THE FAMOUS BARBECUE SAUCE.
AND THE PIMENTO CHEESE WE
GOT HERE--THAT IS HOMEMADE.
AND JUST SMEAR IT ON THERE,
AND THEN GONNA WE'RE PUT IT
IN THE PRESS.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A SOUTH CAROLINA PANINI.
TELL ME ABOUT
THIS CHICKEN STEW.
IT'S THICK, CREAMY,
WITH GOBS AND GOBS OF CHICKEN.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
SOME CHIVES
OR GREEN ONIONS?
MAYBE.
AND THEY'RE EVEN
DOING A REAL-DEAL,
HOMEMADE BREAKFAST.
(Mark) AND WE GOT BREAKFAST
PLATES AND BREAKFAST BISCUITS,
BREAKFAST SANDWICHES, GRITS.
AT A DRIVE-IN,
I'M EATIN' GRITS.
GRITS, SCRAMBLED EGGS--
GREAT BACON, BY THE WAY.
RIGHT.
BUT THE PEACHES--
EXPLAIN IT.
IT'S SOMETHING MR. WHITE STARTED
BACK IN 1946.
IF IT AIN'T BROKE,
DON'T FIX IT.
AND YOU GUYS DEFINITELY FOLLOW
THE TRADITION OF MR. WHITE.
AND THAT MEANS MAKING
TRADITIONAL SOUTHERN ICED TEA,
FILLED WITH SUGAR AND LEMON.
I'VE COME
JUST FOR THE TEA.
I'M COMIN' UP.
OKAY, COME ON UP.
THEY SAY THEY MAKE MORE
THAN ANYPLACE IN THE COUNTRY.
MIGHT MAKE ANYWHERE
FROM ABOUT 600 GALLONS.
SO THIS IS
LIKE YOUR OFFICE?
YES, SIR.
OKAY, SO YOU PUT
THE WATER IN?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, TAKE IT
AND POUR IT IN LIKE THAT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS NOT YOUR
FIRST TEA BATCH, IS IT?
NO, SIR.
SO NOW WE GOT ALL THE SUGAR IN.
WE GOT THE TEA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO NOW YOU MIX IT UP.
YES, SIR.
HOW MANY STIRS?
I DO ABOUT TEN.
TEN STIRS?
TEN GOOD FULL ONES.
I'M TELLING YOU,
IT'S LIKE A WORKOUT!
THAT'S RIGHT.
THANK YOU, SPARTANBURG!
YEAH!
ALL OF THIS TRADITION
KEEPS GETTING PASSED ALONG.
OUR PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
BROUGHT US HERE.
I'VE GROWN UP ON IT.
AND HOW OLD WERE YOU
THE FIRST TIME YOU CAME IN HERE?
(man) PROBABLY
ABOUT 6 MONTHS.
BUT MAYBE THE BIGGEST PART
OF THE BEACON TRADITION
ISN'T THE FOOD.
IT'S THE WAY YOU ORDER IT.
I NEED A HASH A-PLEN-TAY!
WHEN WE COME BACK,
I'M HANGIN' OUT
WITH A GUY WHO'S BEEN
DOING THIS FOR 50 YEARS.
A CHEESEBURGER
WITH A-PLEN-TAY!
THERE YOU GO.
VERY GOOD!
AT THE BEACON
IN SPARTANBURG, SOUTH CAROLINA,
THEY'RE SERVING UP TONS
OF OFF-THE-HOOK FOOD...
WOW!
CHEESEBURGER, FRIED HAM!
JUST LIKE THEY HAVE
FOR OVER 60 YEARS.
THOSE ARE HOT.
BUT AS BIG AND AS GOOD
AS THE MENU IS HERE...
HI. WHAT YOU WANT
TO HAVE, SIR?
FOLKS SAY THE HEART
OF THIS PLACE...
TELL YOU ONE THING.
WE DO NOT HAVE STRANGERS
AT THE BEACON.
IS ONE AMAZING PERSON.
ON THAT MENU,
MY NAME IS J.C.
I'M MORE THAN GLAD
TO HELP YOU.
I GOT A CHEESEBURGER WITH BACON
A-PLENTY ON THE LINE!
J.C. STROBBLE IS
A SPARTANBURG INSTITUTION.
I GOT A CHILI CHEESE...
HE'S BEEN CALLING ORDERS HERE
FOR A HALF A CENTURY.
HE'S LOST HIS EYESIGHT,
BUT NOT HIS ENTHUSIASM
OR HIS ENERGY.
I NEED A HASH A-PLEN-TAY!
J.C., WHAT DID
HE JUST ORDER?
HASH A-PLEN-TAY!
THAT'S A BARBECUE
HASH SANDWICH
SURROUNDED BY FRENCH FRIED
POTATOES AND ONION RINGS.
CALL IT!
TWO GRILLED CHEESE WITH
MAYONNAISE, SMALL ONION RINGS.
I NEED TWO PLAIN CHEESE
WITH MAYONNAISE ON.
CALL IT!
I WANT CHILI CHEESE.
A CHILI CHEESE RIGHT.
YOU'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR HOW MANY YEARS?
ONLY 50.
ONLY 50?
YEAH.
AND IN YOUR SPARE TIME...
HEY. IN MY SPARE TIME,
I GO TO CHURCH
AND I GO HOME
AND GET MY REST.
SAY, "HOT DOG A-PLENTY."
HOLLER IT OUT.
HOT DOG A-PLENTY!
THERE YOU GO.
VERY GOOD!
HOW WAS THAT?
THAT'S GOOD.
OKAY, I GOT THIS GUY.
YOU GOTTA PUT
A LITTLE ACCENTS ON IT.
A LITTLE ACCENT?
YOU GOTTA SAY,
"A-PLEN-TAY."
OH, I GOTTA
DRAW IT OUT? OKAY.
CALL IT.
DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER,
KETCHUP AND MUSTARD ONLY.
DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER
WITH MUSTARD!
THERE YOU GO!
BACON WITH NO TRIM TO-GO!
THERE YOU GO! I LIKE THAT.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S ROCK.
LET'S ROCK!
I GOT A HOT DOG.
I GOT A HOT DOG!
A CHEESEBURGER
WITH A-PLEN-TAY.
WITH A-PLEN-TAY!
THERE YOU GO!
VERY GOOD!
WE'RE READY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL NOW!
I'M ALREADY HOARSE, AND I'VE
ONLY DONE FIVE OF 'EM!
ALL RIGHT. WELL, COME IN ON.
LET'S ROCK.
COME ON!
AND TRY BEING THE GUY
WHO'S FILLING J.C.'s ORDERS
WRITE IT ON THE ORDER PAD.
WHAT? I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT IS!
ONE WHOLE POTATO.
ONE WHOLE POTATO!
TAKE IT DOWN AND GIVE IT
TO THE LADY WITH THE GLOVES.
HURRY BACK.
YOU GOTTA HURRY.
I'M COMIN'! I'M COMIN'!
AND THE ORDERS KEEP COMIN' IN,
'CAUSE SO DO THE CROWDS,
WHO STAY LOYAL
TO THIS PLACE FOREVER.
BUT IT'S JUST ALL IN THE FOOD,
AND THEY GIVE YOU LOTS OF IT.
VISITING YOUR HOMETOWN
AFTER MOVING TO FRANCE?
YOU GOTTA HIT THE BEACON!
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND A HASH
A-PLENTY IN PARIS, FRANCE--
NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
COME ON!
YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE
ISN'T GONNA HAPPEN?
TAKE THIS OUT. OKAY.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND
ANYTHING LIKE THE BEACON
ANYPLACE ELSE--
NOT THAT I'VE EVER SEEN.
60 YEARS IN, AND THEY'RE
STILL ROCKIN' AND ROLLIN'.
GREAT FOOD...
THIS IS WHAT
WE COME FOR.
A ONE-OF-A-KIND EXPERIENCE...
Y'ALL FORM A LINE
HERE, PLEASE.
AND SOME VERY SPECIAL PEOPLE
YOU REALLY OUGHT TO MEET.
A CHEESEBURGER
WITH MUSTARD A-PLEN-TAY!
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
A HASH A-PLEN-TAY.
HAM STEAK A-PLENTY?
A HASH A-PLENTY.
A HA--A WHAT?
HASH A-PLENTY.
A HASH A-PLENTY!
THERE YOU GO!