HI, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR
SOME OF AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) AND IT'S ALL TOTALLY
WORTH THE TRIP
TO AN ISLAND OFF SEATTLE,
WHERE THEY'VE SHIPPED
A 1950s EAST COAST DINER
WITH A WEST COAST MENU
YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS.
THE LEEKS ARE
ACTUALLY FANTASTIC.
PUT THAT ONE ON THERE.
WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
FOR SOME KILLER BARBECUE,
AND GET THIS--
IT'S IN AN AUTO REPAIR SHOP.
GETTING A TUNE-UP
AND SOME RIBS ON THE MENU.
AND IT'S IN THE BRONX.
BARBECUE'S
THE BEST OVER HERE.
WE'RE HEADIN' DOWN
TO SOUTH CAROLINA
FOR FATBACK, CORN BREAD,
AND CHILI BURGERS
LIKE I'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
CALL THAT A MEATBALL
IN NEW YORK CITY.
(man) MEATBALL, RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES,"
WE'LL GO ANYWHERE IN ANY WEATHER
TO FIND YOU THE JOINTS
THAT YOU WANT TO KNOW ABOUT,
LIKE THIS PLACE, MOgridder's,
STUCK IN THE PARKING LOT
OF AN AUTO REPAIR SHOP
IN THE BRONX, NEW YORK.
INSIDE A 35-FOOT TRAILER
THEY'RE SERVING UP
SOME BARBECUE SO GOOD
YOU'LL THINK YOU'RE IN TEXAS
OR MAYBE MEMPHIS...
HERE'S SOME
PIG CANDY, BABY.
NOT...
THE BRONX.
AND CHECK OUT
THE BRONX BRISKET.
(man) THE BRISKET--
IT JUST FALLS APART
IN YOUR MOUTH.
RIBS, PULLED PORK
AND CHICKEN SLOW-COOKED
IN A MASSIVE SMOKER
AND PULLIN' IN THE CROWDS...
BARBECUE'S THE BEST
OVER HERE.
IN EVEN THE LOUSIEST WEATHER--
IT'S JUST THAT GOOD.
TWO RACKS OF RIBS.
TWO RACKS?
TWO RACKS.
TWO SEPARATE CONTAINERS.
PULLED UP TO THE LIGHT
AND LOOKED TO MY RIGHT
AND SAW THE TRUCK AND SAID,
"WHAT?"
HAD MY FIRST ORDER OF RIBS,
AND I'VE BEEN HOOKED SINCE.
(man) IT'S ONLY IN THE BRONX
WHERE YOU CAN
WATCH YOUR TRUCK GET
A FRONT WINDSHIELD
AND GET SOME MEAN
BARBECUE RIBS OUT HERE.
GETTING A TUNE-UP
AND SOME RIBS.
(Guy) YOU CAN ORDER THAT
ON THE MENU?
ON THE MENU.
TODAY'S SPECIAL IS RIBS,
OIL AND A FILTER SPECIAL
FOR $34.95.
(Guy) ANYTHING
I SHOULD TRY?
WE'RE DOIN' A 3-MEAT
COMBO TO GO HOME.
OH, NO, NO, I SAID
ANYTHING ELSE I SHOULD TRY
WHEN I BRING
MY CAR HERE?
OH, WHEN YOU BRING
YOUR CAR HERE?
GET A WINDSHIELD.
I'VE DONE THAT MANY TIMES.
YOU HAVE ANY BACKGROUND
IN RESTAURANT BUSINESS?
NAH.
THE GUY BEHIND ALL OF THIS IS
AUTO SHOP OWNER FRED DONNELLY.
WHAT'S NEXT?
A FEW YEARS BACK, HE TOOK UP
BARBECUING AS A HOBBY...
GRAB MY RIBS.
STARTED BRINGING IN SAMPLES
FOR THE CUSTOMERS,
AND ENDED UP
WITH A TRAILER OUT FRONT
AND A DINING ROOM WHERE
HE USED TO HAVE SERVICE BAYS.
"MOgridder's."
MOgridder's WAS A, UH,
CHILDHOOD NICKNAME
MY COUSIN USED TO CALL ME.
WHAT IS A MOgridder?
WE DON'T KNOW.
HOW DID HE COME UP WITH--
YOU COULD BE A MOgridder.
I'M A MOgridder.
YOU COULD BE A MOgridder. HEY,
MOgridder, WHAT'S HAPPENIN'?
RIBS ARE HAPPENIN'.
IN THE EAST COAST--I DON'T
KNOW HERE SO MUCH ABOUT RIBS.
IN THE SOUTH I HEAR ALL ABOUT
ST. LOUIS OR SPARE RIBS,
AND THEN ON THE WEST COAST,
IT'S ALL ABOUT BABY BACKS.
WHY'D YOU PICK UP
ON THE ST. LOUIS?
I THINK IT HAS A LITTLE MORE
MEAT THAN THE BABY BACK.
YOU THINK?
OH IT HAS--I THINK IT HAS
TONS MORE MEAT.
OKAY, WE RUB 'EM DOWN
IN A DRY RUB--
MOgridder's SEASONING.
IT'S GOT SALT, PEPPER,
GARLIC, PAPRIKA,
AND A FEW THINGS
HE'S KEEPING TO HIMSELF.
HE DRY RUBS THE BRISKET, TOO.
WE'RE GONNA USE
GARLIC FIRST.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
DO YOU NOT NOTICE THAT
A WINDSHIELD JUST WENT THROUGH?
NO.
WE DO ABOUT 40 TO 50
WINDSHIELDS HERE A DAY.
SO A WINDSHIELD COMIN' THROUGH
HERE IN THE MIDDLE OF LUNCH
IS NOT REALLY THAT
BIG OF A DEAL.
IT'S NOT A PROBLEM.
YOU WON'T TASTE IT.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THESE ARE RUBBED DOWN.
GONNA HAVE A NICE BARK.
THESE'LL GO ON 225 DEGREES,
ABOUT TEN HOURS,
BADA-BING?
YEP.
NEVER GET TIRED
OF THAT SMELL.
NOPE, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
OKAY.
WHOA.
ARE YOU THERE?
FRED? AUNTIE EM?
THERE YOU GO, GUY.
THERE'S SOME BRISKET.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, BOY.
ALWAYS LOAD THE BOTTOM FIRST,
OTHERWISE IT'LL TIP,
AND WE'LL HAVE A MESS.
OKAY. BUT WE DON'T
WANT 'EM TOUCHIN',
BECAUSE WE GOTTA LET SMOKE
GO UP BETWEEN 'EM.
AND PUT THAT ONE
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
PORK BUTTS?
YEP, THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, PORK BUTTS--
FAT UP?
FAT UP.
WE'VE GOT OUR BRISKET ON.
WE'VE GOT OUR PORK ON.
WE GOT OUR RIBS ON.
WE'LL THROW SOME CHICKEN ON.
ALL IN TOGETHER,
BUT EACH ITEM WILL SMOKE
FOR A DIFFERENT LENGTH OF TIME.
NOW WHERE ARE YOU
GETTIN' YOUR WOOD FROM?
DON'T SAY "TREES."
WE GET IT
FROM THE SUBURBS OF JERSEY.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF CHERRYWOOD.
THEY HAD A LOT OF, UM,
APPLE ORCHARDS OUT THERE.
I TELL YA, I THINK
MY TEAM MOTLEY QUE
I THINK THEY'RE GONNA
THINK I'M A TRAITOR.
I'M OUT HERE BARBECUING
WITH THIS CAT ON A CORNER
IN THE BRONX.
THIS IS--THIS IS ODD.
BUT NOT SO ODD
WHEN IT'S TASTING TIME.
OH-HO, NOW THE TEST.
SHOULDN'T COME OFF THE BONE.
PEOPLE SAY, "FALL OFF THE BONE."
WELL, IT FALLS OFF
IN A SPOT.
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO TELL
WHERE YOU JUST TOOK A BITE.
NICE BARK--
NICE CRUST UP TOP.
LOW AND SLOW, BABY.
THAT'S GREAT.
WHAT DO WE PULL NEXT?
WELL, WE PULL
THE BRISKET OFF.
CHECK THOSE OUT.
MAN, THAT'S GREAT-LOOKING
BARK ON THERE.
LOOK AT THAT--
ALL NICE AND BLACK.
THAT'S NOT BURNT.
THAT'S FLAVOR.
YEP.
IF YOU CUT IT WITH THE GRAIN,
THEN IT'S GONNA BE
STRINGY AND CHEWY, SO YOU GOTTA
CUT IT AGAINST THE GRAIN.
RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT SMOKE RING
ON THAT.
NICE AND TENDER,
AND THE RUB--THE DRY RUB.
THAT WOULD, UH--
THAT WOULD CHALLENGE
ANY GOOD TEXAS
BRISKET RIGHT THERE.
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
THANK YOU.
SO IS THE PORK BUTT.
IT JUST SLIPS RIGHT OUT.
WHICH MAKES A MEAN
PULLED PORK SANDWICH,
FOR LESS THAN 5 BUCKS.
IF I WAS PAYIN'
FOR ATMOSPHERE,
I'D BE PAYIN' TWICE--
TWICE THE AMOUNT
FOR THE DARN SANDWICH.
AND THE CHICKEN,
RUBBED WITH SALT, PEPPER
AND OLIVE OIL BEFORE SMOKING.
IT COMES WITH
A BARBECUE SAUCE GLAZE--
SAME WITH THE RIBS--BUT THEY'RE
KILLER ALL BY THEMSELVES.
YOU CAN GET THAT
ON THE CORNER OF...
HUNTS POINT
AND RANDALL.
HUNTS POINT AND RANDALL
IN THE BRONX.
WHICH MAKES IT
ONE POPULAR INTERSECTION.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTIN',
JOEY?
WHAT ARE WE HAVIN'?
(woman) TWO RIB PLATTERS.
TWO RIB PLATTERS?
WE DO BETWEEN
150 AND 200 LUNCHES.
THIS PLACE RULES.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD HERE.
THE PULLED PORK, THE RIBS--
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
THE SODA'S IN THE COOLER
ON THE SIDE.
DON'T GO TAKIN' ANY MORE
LIKE THIS GUY GENE DID.
RIGHT.
OKAY.
CAN YOU EAT ALL
THAT?
YOU GONNA BE ABLE TO
FINISH ALL THE RIBS?
AND I THINK I COULD EAT
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
OH, YOU THINK
YOU COULD?
IT'S THAT GOOD.
REALLY?
NO COMMERCIAL BACKGROUND
IN DOING THIS.
NO RESTAURANT EXPERIENCE.
YOU'RE KNOCKIN' IT OUT, MAN.
GOOD STUFF.
THANK YOU.
I MEAN, IT'S A FUNKY JOINT.
I MEAN, WE'RE EATIN' GREAT
BARBECUE OUT OF AN AUTO SHOP,
AND COOKIN' IT ALL OUT OF A--
OUT OF A MONSTER RIG.
I MEAN, IN THE WORLD OF DIVES,
MY FRIEND,
THIS IS--
THIS IS CULINARY DIVE 101.
ULTIMATE DIVE.
WAY TO PULL IT OFF.
NEXT UP, WE'RE HEADING
TO AN ISLAND OFF SEATTLE
WHERE THEY'VE SHIPPED IN
AN AUTHENTIC
EAST COAST DINER...
JUST GREAT DINER FOOD.
FOR SOME DINER COOKIN'
NORTHWEST STYLE.
CORNED BEEF HASH,
BUT WITH SALMON?
I'VE BEEN TO DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES
ALL OVER THIS GREAT COUNTRY,
BUT I GOTTA TELL YA,
THIS IS THE FIRST ONE I'VE EVER
HAD TO TAKE A BOAT TO.
SO WE'RE HEADING TO BAINBRIDGE
ISLAND FROM SEATTLE.
IT'S ABOUT 3 MILES AND
35 MINUTES UNTIL WE'RE DOCKED.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, WHAT WE'RE
HEADED FOR HERE ON THE ISLAND
IS A DINER--
A REAL '50s CLASSIC.
IT WAS SHIPPED OVER HERE
FROM NEW JERSEY
ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO.
IT'S CALLED BIG STAR DINER,
AND THEY SAY THE FOOD HERE
IS WELL WORTH THE TRIP.
JUST GREAT DINER FOOD.
SINGLED OUT, STEPHANIE.
(man) REALLY HITS THE SPOT.
THE ONLY PROBLEM
WITH THIS BURGER
IS GETTING YOUR
MOUTH AROUND IT.
YOU HAVE REAL COMFORT FOOD--
FRIES, BURGER.
THEY HIT ALL THE SPOTS.
ANYONE CARE FOR MUSTARD?
WITH A WAITRESS WHO WILL
REMEMBER YOUR NAME....
HERE YOU GO, CINDY.
A COMFORTABLE PLACE WHERE
YOU CAN COME TO RELAX...
WE SEE OUR FRIENDS HERE,
AND IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A LITTLE CLUB, YOU KNOW?
YOU HANG OUT.
THEY KNOW WHAT WE LIKE TO ORDER.
THEY DON'T EVEN REALLY ASK.
IN A TOTALLY AUTHENTIC PIECE
OF EAST COAST HISTORY.
THE OLD DINER CAR--
THAT'S COOL.
IT'S LIKE GOING BACK
IN TIME, HUH?
IT IS LIKE GOING
BACK IN TIME.
JAY WENCE LEFT
HIS RESTAURANT IN PORTLAND
TO TAKE OVER THE BIG STAR
5 1/2 YEARS AGO,
A FEW YEARS AFTER A COLLECTOR
HAD THE DINER SHIPPED OUT HERE
FROM BACK EAST.
(Jay) IT WAS
IN WILLOW GROVE, PENNSYLVANIA.
IT WAS OPEN IN 1948 TO 1963.
1948? ISN'T THAT WHEN
COLUMBUS CAME OVER?
PRETTY CLOSE TO IT.
IT'S RIGHT AROUND THERE.
JUST TOOK IT APART IN PIECES
AND WROTE NUMBERS ON EACH ONE,
PUT IT IN BOXES AND SENT IT OUT
HERE ON A TRUCK, I BELIEVE.
HOW DO YOU WAIT IN LINE
AT THE FERRY WITH ALL THAT?
AND NOW TOTALLY RESTORED,
THE PLACE REALLY IS A CLASSIC.
AND JAY'S COMMITTED
TO KEEPING IT THAT WAY,
STARTING WITH GOOD,
BASIC DINER COOKING.
WE LIKE TO MAKE
SIMPLE FOOD REALLY WELL.
FRED FLINTSTONE CALLED.
HE WANTS HIS BACON SLABS BACK.
YEAH, OF COURSE.
WHAT DOES THAT COME OFF OF?
I HEAR THEY MAKE, LIKE,
A DIFFERENT SOUP
ALMOST EVERY DAY.
YEAH, THEY DO.
I THINK IT'S SOMEWHERE
IN THE 9.4.
EGGS AND FLOUR...
AND JAY'S NOT AFRAID
TO TWEAK THE OLD STANDARDS.
WANT EGGS, BACON AND WAFFLES?
HAVE A WAFFLE-WICH.
AND HIS HOMEMADE MEATLOAF
HAS A TWIST OF CITRUS.
GOOD LEMON.
LITTLE BIT OF LEMON.
LITTLE BIT OF THYME.
YEAH, RIGHT ON THYME.
HE SERVES IT AS A SANDWICH
ON FRESH SOURDOUGH BREAD.
IT'S STILL REALLY,
REALLY HOT.
MMM.
THAT IS MONEY.
YOU GOTTA TRY A BITE OF THAT.
JAY'S TAKEN THE SAME APPROACH
WITH HIS PANCAKES--
AN OLD FAVORITE
DONE JUST A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
CORNMEAL PANCAKES--
THEY TASTE GREAT.
WHY CORNMEAL PANCAKES?
'COS THEY HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF A LIGHTER TEXTURE
THAN NORMAL BUTTERMILK
PANCAKES.
SO IT'S NOT AS HEAVY--
IT'S ALMOST
A NUTTY FLAVOR.
IT SURE IS A NICE,
GOLDEN-LOOKING PANCAKE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT,
IT'S SOME OF THAT--
THAT CORNMEAL THAT'S
ACTUALLY GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A FRY TO IT, A LITTLE BIT--
A LITTLE BIT OF A, UH--
YOU ACTUALLY BITE
INTO SOMETHING.
WHATEVER YOU ORDER,
JAY'S DOIN' IT HIS WAY,
LIKE THE CHORIZO SCRAMBLE.
HIS CHORIZO'S HOMEMADE.
IT'S A LITTLE SPICY.
IT'S GOOD.
I LIKE IT.
I USE CHORIZO ON MY SHOW,
"GUY'S BIG BITE."
I COOK WITH IT ALL THE TIME.
I THINK THIS IS--
I'M EXCITED.
SKILLED LABOR.
WE MAKE IT WITH PORK SHOULDER
AND POBLANO PEPPERS.
GARLIC?
YEP, GARLIC.
CUMIN.
LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN.
THYME. OREGANO.
LITTLE BIT OF PAPRIKA
AFTER THAT.
SOME APPLE CIDER
VINEGAR.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
THAT'S AN INTERESTING ONE.
THAT GIVES IT A NICE BITE.
HIT IT, BABY.
SMELL THAT!
YOU LIKE IT?
OH, IT SMELLS FANTASTIC.
GREAT.
LOOKS GREAT.
I NEED TO PUT
SOME CHEESE IN HERE
TO FINISH THIS OFF.
ARE THESE OUR POTATOES
DOWN HERE?
THEY ARE.
SO OUR RED POTATO--DO WE HIT 'EM
WITH A LITTLE SEASONING?
IT'S SALT AND PEPPER
AND PAPRIKA. THANKS.
WOW. LOOK AT THAT.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
THAT'S SOME REALLY GOOD CHORIZO.
THANK YOU.
THAT IS REALLY
GOOD CHORIZO.
THANK YOU.
THE CHORIZO SCRAMBLE
IS WHAT I HAD THIS MORNING,
AND THAT'S WHAT I NORMALLY GET.
STEPHANIE!
EVERYBODY'S
GOT THEIR FAVORITE HERE,
BUT FOR MOST FOLKS, THE REAL
FAVORITE IS THE PLACE ITSELF.
IT'S KIND OF WHERE EVERYONE
COMES ON BAINBRIDGE ISLAND.
...WHERE FAMILIES CAN RELAX.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
NOTHING.
OH, GOOD, THEN I'LL HAVE--
CAN I HAVE A DRINK?
NO.
(woman) HE'S HAVING
THE MILK SHAKE.
THAT'S
MY MILK SHAKE.
IT'S A FUN PLACE
TO COME.
...WHERE THE BICYCLE CROWD
CAN PUSH TOGETHER
ALL THE TABLES THEY NEED
TO REFUEL
AFTER RIDING THE ISLAND.
IT TASTES
REALLY GOOD,
AND I WORKED UP
A GOOD APPETITE.
AND TO KEEP THE LOCALS HAPPY,
JAY IS MAKING SURE
HIS EAST COAST DINER MENU
HAS A WEST COAST ISLAND TWIST,
LIKE PACIFIC SALMON HASH.
AS IN CORNED BEEF HASH,
BUT WITH SALMON?
YEAH, IT'S THE SAME
SIMILAR IDEA.
GOT JUST A SPOONFUL
OF ROASTED LEEKS.
OOH, I LOVE LEEKS.
AND I'M GONNA ADD SOME
MUSHROOMS NEXT AND SOME GARLIC.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA USE
FOR THE POTATO FOR THE HASH?
WE'RE GONNA USE
THESE SAME POTATOES.
WOW, THAT IS LOOKING
FANTASTIC.
PRETTY BIG SELLER?
YEAH. WE SELL A LOT,
ESPECIALLY ON THE WEEKENDS.
JUST PUT SOME POACHED EGGS
ON THERE, AND IT'S ALL DONE.
BUT LET ME TAKE
A LOOK AT THAT.
I LIKE THAT THE SALMON
IS IN CHUNKS AND CRISPY.
THIS IS NICE
BIG CHUNKS.
THE LEEKS ARE ACTUALLY
FANTASTIC IN IT.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S THE KICKER
RIGHT THERE.
I WOULD HAVE DEFAULTED
TO A RED ONION,
BECAUSE I'M
A RED ONION FAN,
AND I DON'T THINK
ABOUT LEEKS OFTEN ENOUGH,
BUT I THINK THE LEEK
IS THE WINNER.
AFTER ALL, WHAT'S SALMON
HASH WITHOUT LEEKS
OR SCRAMBLED EGGS
WITHOUT HOMEMADE CHORIZO
OR MEAT LOAF WITHOUT
THE FRESH SOURDOUGH?
IT'S JUST A GREAT PLACE.
HE MAKES A WONDERFUL--
HE MAKES WONDERFUL FOOD,
AND HE REALLY PUTS
HIS HEART INTO IT,
AND IT'S JUST
A GREAT ATMOSPHERE.
HEY, IT'S JUST YOUR BASIC
EAST COAST DINER
WITH YOUR BASIC DINER COOKING
OFF THE COAST OF SEATTLE
AND TOTALLY WORTH THE TRIP.
NEXT STOP, SOUTH CAROLINA,
WHERE THIS GUY BOUGHT
AN ENTIRE RESTAURANT
TO GET THE RECIPE
FOR CHILI BURGERS.
A LITTLE BIT
LIKE A SLOPPY JOE
MEETS A HAMBURGER
MEETS CHILI.
I'M HERE IN GAFFNEY,
SOUTH CAROLINA,
ABOUT 30 MINUTES
NORTH OF GREENVILLE,
WHERE FOOTBALL IS KING,
THE MAIN STREET
IS ALIVE AND WELL,
AND THERE'S A FUNKY
LITTLE JOINT CALLED HAROLD'S
WHERE YOU CAN GET A CHILI BURGER
FOR A BUCK AND A QUARTER.
AND I'LL TELL YA,
THAT'S MY KIND OF JOINT.
MMM, AMAZING.
MORE THAN MESSY, THIS IS
A BURGER WORTH TRAVELING FOR.
I DON'T KNOW. THERE'S
JUST NO OTHER ONE LIKE IT.
NOW THIS IS WHAT WE MAKE
THE BURGER OUT OF?
CORRECT.
SO IT'S NOT
A HAMBURGER PATTY.
NO, WE HAVE
NO HAMBURGER PATTY.
TONY, YOU BEEN
IN NEW YORK CITY BEFORE?
NO, SIR.
WE CALL THAT A MEATBALL
IN NEW YORK CITY.
A MEATBALL, RIGHT.
WE MAKE, PROBABLY, ROLL OUT
10,000 TO 12,000 OF THESE
A WEEK.
(Guy) 10,000
TO 12,000 A WEEK?
TONY LIPSCOMB'S SO PROUD
OF THE MEATBALLS-
TURNED-CHILI BURGERS,
HE SAYS THEY'RE THE REASON HE
BOUGHT THIS PLACE 12 YEARS AGO.
THE SECRET RECIPE,
UNCHANGED SINCE THIS PLACE
OPENED 75 YEARS AGO,
WAS PART OF THE DEAL.
WHAT'S THE MOST YOU EVER
SEEN ANYBODY EAT IN ONE?
I'VE SEEN A GUY EAT 15
IN 1 SITTING.
NO.
IS HE STILL ALIVE?
HE CAME BACK
FOR SUPPER.
NO, HE DIDN'T.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO
MAKE SOME MEATBALLS.
IS THIS MEATBALL MAGIC
THAT I SEE GOING ON HERE?
THIS IS MEATBALL
MAGIC.
WE'LL COOK THESE, AND
THEY'LL BE BROKEN DOWN
FOR THE CHILI.
OKAY.
WE CAN MAKE THOSE
A LITTLE BIGGER.
THESE ARE YOUR ACTUAL
MEATBALLS THAT YOU SEE
THAT ARE
ON THE CHILI BURGERS.
BUT IF THE PILE ON THE LEFT
IS GONNA GET MASHED UP
FOR THE SAUCE,
WHY MAKE 'EM INTO MEATBALLS
TO START WITH?
IT'S THE WAY IT'S BEEN
DONE FOR 75 YEARS,
AND THAT'S THE WAY WE'VE
CONTINUED ON DOING IT.
SO HOW DO
WE COOK THESE?
WELL, THAT'S SOMETHING
I CAN'T SHOW YOU.
THAT'S PART
OF THE SECRET.
THE COOKING METHOD
OF THE MEATBALL THAT'S NOT GONNA
BE A MEATBALL TO MAKE THE SAUCE
IS A METHOD THAT
YOU CAN'T SHOW ME?
EXACTLY.
OKAY. I'LL GO STAND
IN THE CORNER.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU DONE YET, TONY?
ALMOST.
THE PROCESS NOW
IS TO MASH THESE UP.
SO WHAT WE'LL DO IS TAKE
OUR MASHED-UP MEATBALLS.
IT'LL GO IN THE POT.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE COME
OVER HERE
AND GET HOT MEATBALLS THAT
HAVE ALSO BEEN COOKED.
THAT GOES ON TOP.
AND THEN WE GO TO THE STEP
OF MAKING THE SOUP.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER,
A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER, SALT, PEPPER?
EXACTLY.
IT'S ALL COOKED UP
AND THEN POURED OVER THE MEAT.
OKAY, WELL,
LET'S TAKE IT UP FRONT,
AND LET'S GO
MAKE A BURGER.
OKAY.
(Tony) THE ORIGINAL ALL THE WAY
IS MUSTARD, ONIONS AND CHILI.
IT REMINDS ME OF KIND OF
A LITTLE BIT LIKE A SLOPPY JOE-
MEETS-A-HAMBURGER-
MEETS-CHILI.
THERE'S A TON
OF FLAVOR,
AND I REALLY GOTTA SAY
THE KILLER PART
IS THAT STEAMED BUN
AND THE FRESH ONIONS.
OHH.
HI. ARE YOU READY TO ORDER?
DID YOU ORDER? OH, COOL.
ALL THE WAY
WITH SLAW?
NO SLAW, PLEASE.
THERE YOU GO. OH, I'M SORRY,
NO BOOTH SERVICE.
COME OVER HERE
AND GET IT.
(laughing)
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN COMING HERE?
OH, EVER SINCE
I WAS A LITTLE GIRL
WE CAME TO GET
HAMBURGERS HERE.
DO THEY TASTE
THE SAME?
THEY TASTE
THE SAME.
IS THERE ANY OTHER PLACES
LIKE THIS AROUND GAFFNEY?
HMM, I DON'T
THINK SO.
I MEAN, I'VE NEVER
HEARD OF A PLACE
THAT PUTS A MEATBALL
IN CHILI,
THEN PUTS IT ON A BUN AND
CALLS IT A CHILI BURGER.
ME EITHER,
REALLY.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
YOU CAN GET THOSE.
AND AS LONG AS YOU'VE GOT
SOME CHILI SITTING AROUND,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL THROW IT
OVER SOME DOGS, TOO.
TWO HOT DOGS--
CHILI, MUSTARD,
ONIONS, COLESLAW.
FOR HERE?
TO GO, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
TONY, WILL YOU NOW MAKE ME
THE FAMOUS HOT DOG?
GET YOUR HOT DOG,
PUT YOUR MUSTARD DOWN,
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION--
NO MEATBALL.
JUST GET THE CHILI?
OH, WE GOTTA HAVE A LOT
MORE CHILI THAN THAT.
IS THAT--MORE?
YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF, MAN--
REALLY GOOD FLAVOR.
I STILL WISH YOU'D TELL ME
HOW TO MAKE THE CHILI.
BUT I'D HAVE TO BUY
THE PLACE, WOULDN'T I?
YEAH.
THAT WOULD MEAN LEARNING MORE
THAN JUST THE CHILI RECIPE.
YOU SEE, THIS PLACE
ALSO DOES A WHOLE MENU
OF REAL-DEAL
SOUTHERN-JOINT SPECIALTIES.
I DON'T THINK THERE'S ANYTHING
CANNED IN THIS WHOLE PLACE.
NOTHING.
NOTHING?
EVERYTHING'S
HOMEMADE.
THERE'S A RICH CHICKEN STEW...
I SHOULD TRY THAT?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
GOTCHA!
HOMEMADE PIMENTO CHEESE
IN SOME KILLER SANDWICHES...
ACTUALLY, I THINK HIS FAVORITE'S
THE PIMENTO CHEESE.
FRESH CORN MUFFINS
AND SOMETHING CALLED FATBACK.
YOU EVER HAD
THE FATBACK?
UH, YEAH, ON PINTO
BEAN WEDNESDAY.
ON PINTO BEAN
WEDNESDAY?
YEAH.
I'LL HAVE
TO SET MY CALENDAR.
WHAT TIME IS IT? WELL, IT'S
ALMOST PINTO BEAN WEDNESDAY.
AND IT WILL BE
WHEN WE COME BACK.
FATBACK.
OH, DID YOU SEE HIS EYES
LIGHT UP ON FATBACK?
IN GAFFNEY, SOUTH CAROLINA,
THEY'VE BEEN COMING TO HAROLD'S
FOR 75 YEARS NOW...
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
FOR THE CHILI BURGERS, THE DOGS
AND THE EVERYDAY
SOUTHERN FAVORITES
FOLKS AROUND HERE GREW UP WITH,
LIKE THE WEDNESDAY SPECIAL--
PINTO BEANS AND FATBACK.
FATBACK.
OH, DID YOU SEE HIS EYES
LIGHT UP ON FATBACK?
SO TELL ME ABOUT
FATBACK, MICHAEL,
'CAUSE I'VE NEVER
HEARD OF IT BEFORE.
YOU'VE NEVER
HEARD OF FATBACK?
WELL, NO, IT'S RIGHT
NEXT TO FOIE GRAS.
FATBACK?
FATBACK.
PORK FAT?
PORK FAT THAT'S BEEN
SALTED AND CURED.
IT'S SIMILAR
TO BACON.
WE'LL SLICE IT. LIKE
TO GET IT GOOD AND THICK.
I DON'T REALLY SEE
ANY MEAT IN THERE.
THIS IS YOUR MEAT.
THE FAT?
THE FAT.
WE DON'T LIKE TO CALL
ANYTHING FAT AROUND HERE.
NO? WHAT
DO WE CALL THAT?
WELL, THAT'S
THE MEAT.
THAT'S--THAT'S--THAT'S--
THAT'S THE GOOD PART.
THAT'S THE RIND, AND THIS
HAS BEEN CURED IN SALT.
DO YOU WANT
TO BUY A BRIDGE...
SURE.
'CAUSE THAT'S FAT.
OKAY.
OKAY, SO WE TAKE THAT.
WE THROW IT IN THE PAN.
ALL RIGHT, AND THEN
WE THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
AND WHILE
THE FATBACK'S COOKIN'...
SO THESE
ARE PINTO BEANS?
THESE
ARE PINTO BEANS.
TONY'S MAKING
THE PINTO BEANS WITH HAM.
BUY THE WHOLE HAM,
CUT IT UP INTO PIECES
AND PUT IN THREE
TO FOUR GOOD CHUNKS.
IS THAT A MEASURING
TECHNIQUE--CHUNKS?
YES.
OKAY.
TAKE IT BACK OFF THE BONE
AFTER IT'S COOKED,
RETURN IT BACK
TO THE BEANS,
AND YOU HAVE PINTOS
AND HAM AND CORN BREAD.
NOW BRING ON THE FATBACK
AND SOME HOMEMADE
CHOW-CHOW RELISH.
THAT'S GROUND-UP GREEN
TOMATOES, HOT PEPPERS,
VINEGAR.
THIS IS HOW THE PLATE COMES
OUT WHEN I GET THIS?
YES. PUT A LITTLE
CORN BREAD IN IT.
PUT YOUR RELISH IN. PUT A FEW
LITTLE PIECES OF ONION IN.
THAT'S ALL
THE COMBINATIONS TOGETHER.
TAKE A BIG BITE
OF FATBACK.
AND THAT
FINISHES OFF.
I GOTTA TELL YOU, WITH
THE CHOW-CHOW IN THERE,
DUDE, THAT'S--
THAT'S MONEY.
THANK YOU.
IT'S GOOD.
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO SAY, "YEAH,
THAT'S RIGHT. THAT IS MONEY."
THAT'S MONEY.
THAT'S OFF THE HOOK.
THAT'S VERY
OFF THE HOOK.
AND HAROLD'S HAS BEEN
COOKING IT UP SINCE 1932.
FOR TONY, IT'S ALL ABOUT
KEEPING IT THE WAY IT WAS.
FOLKS 'ROUND HERE EXPECT IT.
YOU HAVE SO MANY PLACES NOW
THAT ARE FRANCHISES.
IT'S HARD TO FIND SOMETHIN'
THAT IS ORIGINAL LIKE THIS NOW.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THIS?
I MEAN, IF TONY HADN'T COME
AND TAKEN THIS PLACE OVER--
...A LEGEND
WOULD BE GONE.
I DO NOT BELIEVE
THAT ANYBODY IN GAFFNEY
OR IN THE SURROUNDING
SOUTH CAROLINA AREA
WOULD BE ABLE
TO LIVE WITH THE FACT
OF THIS PLACE
EVER CHANGING.
SO MY BROTHER, I GOTTA
HAND IT TO YOU, MAN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
CONGRATULATIONS.
AWESOME JOB.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS WE GOTTA HIT.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(horn honking)
OH, GOSH.
UH-OH.