HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP--LOCAL LEGENDS,
LIKE THE DINER IN MAINE
THAT'S UP ON STILTS...
30 FEET IN THE AIR!
WHERE THE FOOD'S
ON A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL, TOO.
WHAT DO PEOPLE SAY?
THEY COME IN,
"I WANT FRENCH TOAST... NA.
BUT I'LL HAVE THE DUCK."
THE LEGENDARY BARBECUE JOINT
IN WHAT USED TO BE
AN OKLAHOMA CITY GAS STATION...
COME ON WITH IT!
WITH KICKIN' RIBS
THAT BRING IN FANS
FROM MILES AWAY.
WHEN WE GET TO OKLAHOMA CITY,
IT'S THE BEST.
AND THIS 300-SEAT BEAUTY
IN HYDE PARK, NEW YORK,
A LOCAL LEGEND
FOR BAKING EVERYTHING--
I MEAN EVERYTHING.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF,
BUDDY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
IN 1946,
THE WORCESTER DINER CAR COMPANY
BUILT DINER CAR NUMBER 790
AND DELIVERED IT RIGHT HERE
TO GARDENER, MAINE.
NOW UNDER ITS FOURTH OWNER,
THIS LOCAL LEGEND
IS SERVING UP WAY MORE
THAN TRADITIONAL DINER FARE.
(bell dings)
(man) THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
LOOKING FOR.
I TRAVEL AROUND
WITH THIS SPOON.
OH, MAN,
THIS IS GREAT.
THEY'VE GOT ALL
THE OLD FAVORITES...
AND MEATLOAF.
EVIDENTLY
YOU DIDN'T LIKE IT...
NO, NO--
BECAUSE YOU CLEANED
THE WHOLE THING.
AND SOME WITH A TWIST.
BANANA WALNUT PANCAKES?
BANANA WALNUT PANCAKES.
WHO'S RECIPE IS THIS?
OUR RECIPE THAT WE'VE HAD
FOR YEARS.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS.
THIS I GET A KICK OUT OF.
HERE YOU ARE AT THE DINER.
CHILI DOG, MAC AND CHEESE...
YEAH.
LET ME HAVE A DOUBLE
CHEESEBURGER, HAVE SOME FRIES,
BUT THEN LET'S
STEP RIGHT IN
AND GET SOME
SZECHUAN BEEF SAUTE.
YOU CAN BLAME THAT
ON KENNETH.
KENNY. OH, JEEZ.
KENNETH'S
A SEATTLE TRANSPLANT
WHO BROUGHT SPECIALS LIKE SPICY
ASIAN NOODLES WITH SHRIMP,
LAMB TAGINE WITH COUSCOUS,
AND CHICKEN MARVEA WITH PRUNES,
GREEN OLIVES AND GARLIC.
THERE'S SO MANY
INTERESTING THINGS.
CREOLE BEANS AND RICE.
DELISH.
NOW DO THEY GIVE YOU
PRETTY FREE REIN
OF WHAT YOU WANT TO DO?
I GET FREE REIN
OF WHATEVER I WANT TO DO.
IT'S WHATEVER
I FEEL LIKE DOING.
HE'LL BUY WHATEVER
I WANT, AND...
'CAUSE THE OWNERS
ARE KIND OF BOZOS. I MEAN...
YEAH.
(mutters)
WELL, NO,
'CAUSE I'M AN OWNER. I KNOW.
NOW IS THIS YOUR RECIPE?
THIS IS MY RECIPE.
YOU WROTE THIS?
THIS IS MY CONCOCTION,
YES.
YOUR CONCOCTION.
IT'S A GREEK STUFFED
FLANK STEAK ROULADE.
START WITH A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER.
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU HAVE FRESH-
GROUND THIS PEPPER YOURSELF.
ABSOLUTELY.
BROTHER, I HAVE
GOTTA TELL YOU,
THAT IS IN IT TO WIN IT.
A LITTLE GARLIC,
SPINACH
AND A LITTLE RED PEPPER.
ROASTED RED BELLS.
WE'VE GOT SOME
ARTICHOKE HEARTS HERE.
MARINATED OR...
YES, THEY ARE MARINATED WITH
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL, WHITE WINE.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
AND THEN SOME FETA.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO THERE WE ARE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE TUCK.
YOU EVER ROLL SUSHI?
YES, DEFINITELY.
LOVE SUSHI, DUDE.
YOU HAD THE--
LOVE THE SUSHI.
YOU HAD THE SUSHI ROLL--
YOU HAD THE MAKI ROLL
GOING ON, MAN.
THIS WILL GO
ON THE MENU--
NOW HOW LONG HAS YOUR
SPECIAL BEEN RUNNING?
I RUN IT UNTIL IT RUNS OUT,
AND THEN I'LL TAKE A BREAK
FOR A COUPLE OF WEEKS OR I'LL
STUFF IT WITH SOMETHING ELSE,
JUST CHANGE IT UP. NEVER KEEP
THE SAME ONE CONSTANTLY.
CHECK THAT OUT.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
FETA'S NICE.
TOTALLY DOWN WITH THAT.
THAT'S GONNA BE A HIT.
NICE BALANCE.
COOKED PERFECTLY.
THAT'S BANANAS. MM!
BANANAS IS GOOD.
THE ROULADE
AND ALL THE WILD NEW DISHES
HAVE BEEN A BIG HIT
WITH THE LOCALS,
WHO HAVE BEEN COMING
TO THE A1 FOR 60 YEARS.
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
HOW YOU DOING?
MIKE GIBERSON
IS THE FOURTH OWNER.
HIS DAD WAS NUMBER THREE,
AND THE PLACE ITSELF--
KNOWN AS "HEALD'S DINER"
WHEN IT WAS FIRST OPENED
BACK IN '46--
REALLY IS A LOCAL LEGEND,
SET UP ON 30-FOOT STILTS
NEXT TO THE BRIDGE
OVER THE COBBOSSEECONTEE STREAM
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF TOWN.
THEY PULLED THIS FLATBED UP,
AND THEY JUST SLID THIS
ON HUGE PLANKS INTO PLACE.
RIGHT ON TOP OF IT?
RIGHT ON TOP
OF THE STEEL.
THE TILE...
YEP.
ORIGINAL?
YEAH. YES.
THE COUNTER ORIGINAL.
THE BOOTHS ORIGINAL?
THE BOOTHS ORIGINAL.
ALL MAHOGANY.
WHERE DO YOU FIND
THE LITTLE LETTERS?
WE CAN STILL BUY
THE WHITE LETTERS,
BUT I CAN NO LONGER
BUY THE RED LETTERS.
THOSE RED LETTERS
ARE PRECIOUS TO ME.
AND SO IS MIKE'S GOAL
OF KEEPING THE CUSTOMERS HAPPY.
OH, WOW.
(Michael) WE HAD TO ATTRACT
THE YOUNGER CLIENTELE...
UNBELIEVABLE.
AND PEOPLE WHO WERE MORE
INTERESTED IN FOOD,
PLUS WE WANTED TO COOK
THE KIND OF FOOD WE LIKE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD FOOD, AND YOU
GET TO TRY DIFFERENT THINGS.
WHEN YOU CAN SIT DOWN
AND HAVE SOME...
LEEK STRUDEL.
LEEK STRUDEL,
WHICH YOU DON'T FIND ON EVERY
MENU, IN CASE YOU DIDN'T KNOW.
OR MAYBE SOME
MOJITO GLAZED DUCK.
I MEAN, WHAT DO
PEOPLE SAY?
THEY COME IN,
"I WANT FRENCH TOAST... NA.
BUT I'LL HAVE THE DUCK."
"I'LL HAVE THE DUCK." WELL,
BECAUSE EVERYBODY WANTS DUCK.
BEST THING I'VE EVER
HAD HERE, REALLY.
REALLY?
BUT I'VE HAD SOME...
TERRIBLE DUCK?
BAD DUCK EXPERIENCES.
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY--
I THINK EVERYBODY'S
BEEN THROUGH THE DUCK--
WHEN DUCK GOES WRONG.
IT'S PAN-SEARED...
NOW THAT--YOU COULDN'T BE
ANY HAPPIER WITH THAT.
THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
FINISHED IN THE OVEN...
WE'RE DOWN
WITH THE DONE DUCK.
AND TOPPED WITH KENNETH'S
MOJITO GLAZE.
RUM...
RUM.
BROWN SUGAR...
BROWN SUGAR.
WHEN THOSE COOK DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
YOU GO AHEAD AND ADD
IN THE MINT.
I ACTUALLY KEEP SUGAR
ON THE SIDE WITH MINT IN IT
SPECIFICALLY
FOR THIS PURPOSE.
THE OILS ARE EXCRETED
INTO THE SUGAR.
NOW HOW LONG DID YOU LET THAT
MINT AND THAT SUGAR HANG OUT?
LET IT SIT AROUND FOR ABOUT
TWO WEEKS, THREE WEEKS.
REALLY?
YEP.
YOU'RE PUTTING IT ON.
TRYING TO DO
SOMETHING NICE.
OH, IT'S MORE THAN NICE.
THAT'S DUCK-LICIOUS.
NICE JOB, BROTHER,
REAL NICE JOB.
THAT'S DUCK DONE RIGHT.
I'M BETTER THAN
THE DUCK THIS TIME.
YOU ARE BETTER THAN THE DUCK.
I CONQUER YOU, DUCK!
BUT DON'T THINK
THIS CLASSIC DINER'S
IGNORING THE DINER CLASSICS.
(Michael) I'VE SAID
TO THE STAFF OVER THE YEARS,
"GET A MENU IN PEOPLE'S HANDS
IMMEDIATELY."
YOU CAN'T LET 'EM THINK
WE JUST HAVE MOJITO DUCK BREAST
AND ASIAN CORN FRITTERS.
'CAUSE A LOT OF FOLKS
JUST WANT A BURGER
OR SOME REAL DEAL
HOMEMADE HASH.
THAT'S BANANAS!
I DON'T OFTEN DINE
RIGHT OFF OF THE FLAT TOP,
BUT, YOU KNOW...
THAT'S SOME MONEY HASH.
(man) THAT'S GOOD HASH.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD HASH.
THAT IS FANTASTIC HASH.
WHIPPED UP
BY BOB THE HASH MAN,
WHO'S BEEN WORKING HERE
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
THAT RECIPE'S IN MY HEAD.
SO YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE
THIS WRITTEN DOWN?
NO.
SO YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
THAT CAN MAKE IT.
RIGHT NOW.
OH, SEE. SO THAT'S
JOB SECURITY RIGHT THERE.
AND YOU CAN'T GET ANY DEEPER
INTO CLASSIC DINER COMFORT FOOD
THAN KENNETH'S
CHICKEN POTPIE,
FROM FRESH POACHED CHICKEN
PULLED APART BY HAND...
IT JUST HAS MORE
AUTHENTIC FEEL TO IT.
FRESH VEGGIES...
LITTLE SAGE.
HOMEMADE ROUX
AND A SCRATCH-MADE CRUST.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
TOP IT ONLY?
WE'RE NOT PUTTING
ANY CRUST ON THE BOTTOM?
NO BOTTOM CRUST,
TOP CRUST ONLY.
IT'S OVER. SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY, DUDE.
YOU WANT A POTPIE.
YOU DON'T WANT--
NO, I WANT CARBO-JUNKIE.
BUT THEY DO LOOK GOOD.
HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT IT?
DUDE, I THINK THE SAGE
IS THE KEY RIGHT THERE.
EVEN WITH NO
BOTTOM CRUST?
I'M TRYING
TO GET OVER IT.
HOWEVER MANY CRUSTS, WHAT
THEY'RE DOING HERE AT THE A1--
THE OLD STUFF
AND THE NEW STUFF--
REALLY IS KEEPING THEM
A LOCAL LEGEND.
ROOT BEER AND DUCK--YOU CAN
ONLY DO THAT AT THIS DINER.
FULFILLING YOUR DREAM
OF HAVING A PLACE.
YEAH.
I MEAN, HOW DOES THAT
MAKE YOU FEEL?
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S BEEN REWARDING.
WE'VE MET TONS OF PEOPLE
AND MADE GREAT FRIENDS,
AND IT'S, YOU KNOW,
IT'S OUR LIFE,
SO WHY NOT MAKE IT FUN
AND HAVE FUN DOING IT?
NEXT UP, A LOCAL LEGEND
IN OKLAHOMA CITY BARBECUE
IN WHAT USED TO BE
A GAS STATION.
THE FILLIN' PUMPS USED TO BE OUT
THERE, BUT NOW THEY'RE INSIDE.
YEAH, WE FILLIN'
YOU UP IN HERE, BABY.
I'M HERE IN OKLAHOMA CITY,
RIGHT BETWEEN DALLAS
AND KANSAS CITY,
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF AMERICA.
NOW CHECK OUT WHAT I'VE FOUND.
THIS PLACE HERE
USED TO BE A GAS STATION,
BUT NOW IT'S MAKING SOME
OUTRAGEOUS RIBS
AND INCREDIBLE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WELCOME TO OKLAHOMA CITY.
THIS IS OUR HOUSE.
I LIKE IT, MAN.
IT'S YOUR HOUSE
WHILE YOU'RE HERE.
AND HOME TO CHARLES SMITH'S
TOTALLY OFF THE HOOK...
GOT SOME MORE LOVE
COMIN' THROUGH.
DOWN-HOME O.K.C. BBQ...
IT'S THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
SERVED UP
IN AN OLD GAS STATION.
THE FILLIN' PUMPS USED TO BE OUT
THERE, BUT NOW THEY'RE INSIDE.
YEAH, WE FILLIN' YOU UP
IN HERE, BABY.
THAT ONE I WILL TAKE.
THAT'S THE FIRST ONE
OF THE MORNING.
THAT WAS
A LITTLE BIT HARDER.
I'M SORRY.
I'M SO STRONG.
THIS IS A DEMONSTRATION
BARBECUE KITCHEN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
EVERYTHING'S OPEN-FACED.
WE SHOWIN' YOU
WHAT WE WORKIN' WITH.
WE HAVE NOTHIN' TO HIDE.
SAUCE EVEN COME ON THE SIDE.
THIS IS THE BEST BARBECUE
ACROSS THE UNITED STATES.
YOU NAME IT,
THEY'RE MAKING IT,
FROM RIBS AND BRISKET TO
BARBECUE CHICKEN AND HOT LINKS.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
THE VEGETARIAN PLATTER HERE?
NO.
(man) NO, WHAT'S THAT?
LEO'S HAS BEEN SERVING UP
AUTHENTIC BARBECUE SINCE 1974.
DOUBLE BEANS ON BOTH?
WE LIKE TWO HOGS
GOIN' TO THE TROUGH.
WE START OUT FRESH
EVERY DAY... EVERY DAY.
YOU HAVE TO, MAN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK MAKES
GREAT BARBECUE?
GREAT BARBECUE
COMES FROM PATIENCE,
HAVIN' A RELATIONSHIP
WITH YOUR SMOKERS.
CAN YOU HEAR IT?
YOU HEAR IT TALKIN'?
IS THAT THE RIGHT SOUND?
THAT'S IT RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THE RIGHT SOUND?
THAT'S IT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
WHAT REAL BARBECUE IS.
INSIDE THAT PIT'S
REAL BARBECUE.
GOOD MORNIN', BABIES.
THE PITS HAVE BEEN AROUND
SINCE THE BEGINNING.
MY DAD BUILT 'EM. WE FEED
THE WOOD IN RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT, SO YOU OFFSET IT.
UH-HUH, AND THEN INDIRECT HEAT
COMES RIGHT UP THROUGH HERE.
AND SLOW-COOKS THE MEAT.
'CAUSE LOVE DON'T
COME IN A HURRY.
GOT AN HOUR
TO SHOWTIME.
SHOW TIME IS 11:00
WHEN THE LUNCH RUSH HITS,
AND YOU JUST GOTTA TRY...
THE RIBS.
RIBS? LOOK AT HIM.
HE'S NOT EVEN--
"JUST KEEP TALKIN', BUDDY.
I'M GONNA EAT."
LITTLE OF THIS SEASONING
ON HERE.
ALL WE'RE SIMPLY USING
IS BLACK PEPPER AND SALT.
PUTTIN' THESE
LITTLE PIGGIES ON.
WHAT DO YOU SMOKE WITH?
HICKORY.
JUST HICKORY?
REALLY?
EXACTLY. THEY STARTIN'
TO GET THERE. SEE?
THEY'RE STARTING
TO GET A LITTLE DARK THERE.
AM I JUST GETTING A LOT
OF THE SMOKE IN MY FACE, OR--
YEAH, 'CAUSE YOU'RE
LOOKING RIGHT INTO IT.
YOU GOTTA GO UNDER. UNDER, BABY.
GO UNDER THE SMOKE!
MOST PEOPLE DOING BARBECUE
FROM THE ROCKIES OVER
ARE USING BABY BACK RIBS.
RIGHT.
OKAY, AND YOU'RE NOT COOKING
WITH BABY BACK RIBS.
NO.
AND THE REASON YOU COOK WITH
A SPARE RIB IS BECAUSE WHY?
I JUST LIKE THE PRODUCT
THAT MY DAD STARTED.
THEY'RE THE WAY THEY SHOULD BE--
MESSY, TENDER, DELICIOUS, JUICY.
CHARLES BEGAN LEARNING IT ALL
FROM HIS DAD
WHEN HE WAS JUST A KID.
I WAS 10 YEARS OLD.
IT WAS 1974, BUT THE DAY
HE OPENED THOSE DOORS
IS WHEN I KNEW WHAT I WANTED
TO DO WHEN I GREW UP.
REALLY?
THAT'S WHEN I KNEW.
THAT WAS IT?
IT WAS WHEN IT HIT ME.
SO THIS IS
YOUR POPS RIGHT HERE?
THAT WAS MY DAD, MM-HMM.
I TRIED MY BEST
NOT TO CHANGE ANYTHING
ON THE CONCEPTS
OF WHAT MY DAD STARTED.
IS THIS LOVE
THAT I'M FEELIN'?
THE BRISKET'S STILL SLOW-COOKED
FOR 17 TO 18 HOURS.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
SCARES ME WHEN HE GETS
THE... GOING.
AND THERE'S CHICKEN...
PUT THE SEASONING ON THERE,
PUT THE LOVE ON IT.
IT'S AMAZING.
IT'S THE BEST.
IS THE CHICKEN
THE BOMB?
THE CHICKEN'S GREAT.
AND HOT LINKS...
THAT IS A GOOD HOT LINK.
WOW, THAT'S A HOT HOT LINK.
EVEN BARBECUED BOLOGNA.
I LOVE BOLOGNA. IT'S WAY GOOD.
I'LL USE MY FINGERS.
AND THEN THERE'S THE SAUCE.
THEY HAVE TWO DIFFERENT
TYPES OF SAUCES.
I LOVE THE SPICY ONE.
I'M NOT MAN ENOUGH
TO HANDLE THE HOT ONE.
NO. COME ON.
WHAT WE DO
IS WE SLOW-COOK THIS
FOR ABOUT A DAY AND A HALF
TO TWO DAYS.
IT SMELLS INCREDIBLE.
NOW IS THIS
YOUR DADDY'S RECIPE?
OF COURSE.
EITHER TOMATO SAUCE
OR KETCHUP IN THERE.
I'M DEFINITELY CATCHING
THE VINEGAR.
FAMILY SECRET RECIPE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GIVE ME THIS, ARE YOU?
THEN EVERYBODY WILL DO IT,
AND THEY WON'T
WANT TO COME SEE ME.
I DON'T THINK ANYBODY
HAS A CHARLES
THAT IS DOING THIS--
NO, YOU'RE ONE OF A KIND.
DON'T BITE YOUR
FINGER, BABY.
WOW. NOW WE'LL GO HOT.
OKAY.
(raspy voice)
I CAN HANDLE THIS.
HEY... SAUCE!
OKAY, I'M SORRY.
SORRY, BABY, SORRY.
DO YOU SEE THE GUY
IN THE WHITE TIE, HUH?
JUST PUT SOME SAUCE
ON IT FOR ME.
JUST--IF YOU DO IT
I'LL FEEL A LOT BETTER.
NOW THERE'S ONE OTHER ITEM
THAT'S A BIG PART OF KEEPING
LEO'S A LOCAL LEGEND.
THE CAKE IS MY FAVORITE.
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
THE CAKE
IS THE WHOLE REASON...
IT'S THE STRAWBERRY
BANANA CAKE.
CHARLES SAYS ON DELIVERIES
HE MAKES SURE TO CARRY 'EM
SO PEOPLE CAN SEE 'EM.
I CAN GO ANYWHERE.
I CAN GO IN THE STATE CAPITOL
WITHOUT MY LOGO
OR ANYTHING ON IT.
IF THEY CAN SEE THAT
STRAWBERRY BANANA CAKE,
THEY'LL SAY, "OH! LEO'S!"
WE PUT A FREE SLICE OF THIS
WITH EVERY DINNER HERE AT LEO'S.
NO!
YEAH.
NOW WHAT IS THE ICING
MADE OF?
IT'S MADE OF, UH,
SOME...
DON'T SAY, "LOVE."
OF COURSE.
LOVE IS IN EVERYTHING.
WE PUT OUR BANANAS
IN THE MIDDLE LAYER.
SLICING THE BANANA.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT ON TOP.
NOW WE'RE GOING
WITH THE STRAWBERRIES.
JUST LIKE THAT.
THEN WE GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS ENTICING ICING,
AND WE DRIZZLE IT
OVER THE TOP LIKE SO.
I MEAN, IT'S GREAT.
NO FORK NECESSARY, RIGHT?
NOT ALL THE TIME.
THE CAKE IS A FAMILY RECIPE,
AND CHARLES IS KEEPING
THE WHOLE PLACE
A FAMILY OPERATION.
AUNT COOKIE'S MAKING SALADS.
AUNT FLO IS WAITING TABLES.
THAT'S MOM AT THE COUNTER.
AND NEPHEW REGGIE IS GETTING
THE SAME TRAINING
CHARLES GOT FROM HIS DAD.
YOU HEAR IT
TALKIN' TO US?
YOU'RE--JUST BY TOUCHING IT--
YOU'RE SQUEEZING THE MEAT.
YOU CAN JUST KIND OF TELL--
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S HOW WE KNOW.
HE'S GONNA BE A JEDI.
HE'S GOING TO THE--
HE'S GOING TO BE A JEDI.
HE'S GOING
TO THE GOOD SIDE.
FOR CHARLES, THE WAY TO KEEP
THIS PLACE A LOCAL LEGEND
IS SIMPLE--JUST KEEP DOING
WHAT HIS DAD DID.
AND I ASK HIM,
"WHAT'S THE SECRET."
HE WON'T GIVE IT TO YOU,
WILL HE?
OH, NO,
HE'S GIVING IT TO ME.
OH, HE WILL?
HE KEEPS TELLING ME,
"IT'S LOVE."
I JUST LOVE IT SO MUCH
TO WHERE THIS IS EASY FOR ME.
I CAN DO THIS BASICALLY
ALMOST WITH MY EYES CLOSED.
AND YOU LOVE DOING IT.
I LOVE DOING IT.
I ENJOY DOING IT.
GLAD Y'ALL CHOSE LEO'S.
WE'LL--
LET ME CHECK.
ARE ALL YOUR FINGERS
STILL THERE?
UH, NO.
NEXT UP, THIS GLEAMING LOCAL
LEGEND IN HYDE PARK, NEW YORK,
WHERE THEY'RE SCRATCH-BAKING
CAKES, PIES
AND DINNER ROLLS
THE SIZE OF A TRUCK.
I COULDN'T HAVE DINNER
IF I ATE THAT.
YOU KNOW WHEN YOU'RE LUCKY
ENOUGH TO FIND A PLACE
THAT BAKES THEIR OWN PIES,
CAKES AND BREADS?
IT'S USUALLY A LITTLE
MOM-AND-POP JOINT.
WELL, THE EVEREADY DINER
IN HYDE PARK, NEW YORK,
IS THE MAJOR EXCEPTION
TO THAT RULE.
THIS PLACE IS HUGE,
SERVES UP TO 1,000 MEALS A DAY,
AND THE GUYS IN CHARGE
ARE A BAND OF COUSINS...
UNCLE DENNY.
TOMMY--SON OF UNCLE DENNY.
ALEX--COUSIN OF TOMMY.
COSTA--SON OF UNCLE TEDDY,
THE COUSIN OF ALEX.
ALL COMMITTED
TO THE SAME THING--
IT JUST DOESN'T TASTE AS GOOD
IF IT'S NOT HOMEMADE.
SO GUESS WHAT?
IT'S HOMEMADE.
BROWN SUGAR INSIDE.
FROM CHEESECAKE
TO FOCACCIA
IN UNCLE TEDDY'S BAKERY
IN THE BASEMENT.
THESE ARE DINNER ROLLS?
YEAH, FOR DINNER.
I COULDN'T HAVE DINNER
IF I ATE THAT.
ALL KINDS OF COMFORT FOOD
AND BURGERS,
AND CHECK OUT THE MOZZARELLA
AND TOMATOES WITH PESTO.
THERE YOU GO.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
LIKE, YOU KNOW THE FOOD'S GONNA
BE GOOD. IT'S GONNA BE FRESH.
THEY EVEN MAKE THEIR OWN
BREADCRUMBS
FOR THE MOZZARELLA STICKS
THEY COVER.
WE'VE BEEN MAKING IT FROM
SCRATCH HERE FOREVER,
SO THEY GET THE REAL THING.
IT'S BEEN THAT WAY SINCE 1972,
WHEN TEDDY
AND HIS BROTHER-IN-LAW,
WHO CAME OVER FROM GREECE,
OPENED UP A 30-SEAT DINER.
23 YEARS LATER,
THEY TORE IT DOWN
AND PUT UP THIS ONE
WITH 300 SEATS.
YOU GO INTO POUGHKEEPSIE
OR WOPPINGERS FALLS,
YOU SAY "EVEREADY,"
PEOPLE KNOW WHERE IT IS.
I CAME HERE FOR BREAKFAST
WITH MY HUSBAND
AND LUNCH WITH MY KIDS.
IN HYDE PARK,
THIS IS THE DINER.
WHERE ELSE
ARE THEY STILL MAKING
A PANCAKE BATTER
FROM SCRATCH?
15 EGGS?
15 EGGS.
AND WE PUT IN
A GALLON OF MILK.
GALLON OF MILK.
GALLON OF BUTTERMILK.
DO YOU MILK THE COW.
NO, NO, NO.
JUST CHECKIN'.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY.
YOU MAKE ALL THE BREAD,
ALL THE CAKES--THE WHOLE THING.
NO, THAT'S THE ONLY THING
WE DON'T MAKE.
AND WHAT ELSE?
BROWN SUGAR,
SOME REGULAR SUGAR.
VANILLA POWDER
AND SOME MALTED MILK.
YOU'VE GOT MORE
INGREDIENTS IN HERE
THAN I THINK ANYBODY WOULD
IMAGINE GOES INTO A PANCAKE.
IS THIS WHAT YOUR DAD
WAS MAKING FOR YOU
WHEN YOU WERE
A KID AT HOME?
UH, NO.
OR DID YOU JUST EAT
HERE ALL THE TIME?
I--YEAH,
I WAS ALWAYS HERE.
THAT WAS IT?
WE HAD NO FOOD AT HOME.
I WAS JUST ALWAYS HERE.
MAN, WHEN I WAS A KID,
I WANTED THE LITTLE TINY--
THE SILVER DOLLAR ONES?
THE SILVER DOLLAR ONES.
I LIKE THAT--
I LIKE THOSE, TOO.
THAT'S MINE RIGHT THERE.
IT'S ALMOST A LITTLE BIT
STILL WET,
SO IT'LL ALMOST RUN
A LITTLE BIT WHEN YOU FLIP IT,
BUT THAT'S THE CONSISTENCY
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
YES, YES.
NOW MINE ARE READY TO GO.
YEAH, YOURS ARE
READY TO GO.
OKAY.
SEE? THAT'S--THAT RIGHT
THERE IS WHAT YOU WANT.
THAT'S OPTIMUM.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR.
YES.
NOW WHAT DO YOU TYPICALLY
SERVE WITH A PANCAKE HERE?
A PANCAKE? USUALLY SERVE
STRAWBERRY BUTTER,
REGULAR BUTTER, YOU KNOW.
STRAWBERRY BUTTER?
DO YOU GUYS MAKE THAT?
YES.
WOW. NICE, LIGHT AND AIRY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT HAS A TON
OF FLAVOR IN IT.
YOU CAN EVEN GET 'EM TOPPED
WITH HOT APPLES
FROM THEIR OWN ORCHARD
OR BANANAS--
THE KIND OF DISH YOU WON'T FIND
AT MOST DINERS.
THEN AGAIN,
YOU WON'T FIND A FULL BAR
AT MOST DINERS EITHER.
SO SOMEONE CAN COME AND HAVE
PANCAKES AT 9:00 AT NIGHT
AND A GIN AND TONIC?
YEAH.
COMIN' THROUGH.
AND WHEN IT COMES
TO THE FOOD...
BURGER.
BREAKFAST. CHICKEN.
BREAKFAST. PANCAKES.
I MADE THE PANCAKE
BATTER TODAY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE CROWD HERE
KNOWS THEIR STUFF.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE
TO COME AROUND.
CHECK OUT THE WAY THEY DO
A DINER CLASSIC
LIKE SHORT RIBS.
THIS IS COMFORT FOOD
RIGHT HERE, YOU KNOW?
YEAH.
DID YOU GO TO SCHOOL
FOR CULINARY?
THIS WAS MY SCHOOL.
THIS WAS YOUR SCHOOL?
YEAH,
THIS WAS MY SCHOOL.
WHAT DID YOU GET
YOUR DEGREE IN?
POLITICAL SCIENCE.
POLY SCI. YOU'RE WORKIN'--
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU'RE TRYING TO GET THOSE
CARROTS AND CELERY TO GET ALONG.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
AND PHILOSOPHY OF,
"WHY SHOULD THEY GET ALONG?"
EXACTLY.
OKAY, SO WE TAKE
THE SHORT RIBS.
YOU BASICALLY WANT
TO SEASON 'EM.
YOU TAKE A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
I LOVE THE FRESH CRACKED.
YOU TAKE SOME FRESH HERBS.
I USUALLY LIKE TO DO ROSEMARY,
THYME AND SAGE.
SO RUB THOSE ALL IN...
RUB THOSE ALL IN.
PACK 'EM DOWN ON, OKAY?
YEP.
AND THEN WE DREDGE 'EM
IN A LITTLE FLOUR.
JUST A ROUGH-CHOP
OF SOME CELERY, CARROTS, FENNEL.
DO A LITTLE ONION.
NOW DEGLAZE IT
WITH RED WINE.
DEGLAZE IT
WITH A RED WINE.
WE WANT TO PICK UP
ALL THE TIDBITS--
ALL THE FLAVORS
THAT ARE ON THERE.
ABSOLUTELY.
JUST POUR IT RIGHT ON TOP.
LITTLE BROWN SAUCE.
THEN WE TAKE SOME
PLUM TOMATOES--
SAN MARZANO.
AND THIS RECIPE
WAS HANDED DOWN?
THIS WAS HANDED DOWN,
MAN.
THREE HOURS...
THREE HOURS.
COVERED,
ONE HOUR UNCOVERED, AND...
THAT'S CAPITAL T
TENDER, BUDDY.
YEAH, MAN.
BUT I THINK IT GOES DOWN
TO THE WHOLE PRINCIPLE
ABOUT HOW YOU GUYS ARE DOING
FOOD AT THE EVEREADY.
JUST GOOD FOOD--
GOOD FOOD TO MAKE YOUR
BELLY FEEL GOOD, YOU KNOW?
THIS WILL MAKE YOUR BELLY
FEEL GOOD...
AND THIS AND THIS.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
I'M CHECKING OUT THE SECRET
OF THE BAKERY IN THE BASEMENT.
I WAS GONNA HELP YOU WITH IT,
BUT IT LOOKED LIKE YOU HAD IT.
WE'RE AT THE EVEREADY DINER
IN HYDE PARK, NEW YORK.
THIS IS LIKE THE CAESAR PALACE
OF DINERS.
IT'S AN INSTITUTION, MAN.
IT GLOWS, MAN.
IT'S LIKE VEGAS.
AND CUSTOMERS KEEP CASHING IN
ON A 35-YEAR TRADITION
OF GREAT HOME COOKING.
THEIR FOOD
IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
MY FAVORITE IS
THE CHICKEN CAESAR WRAP
WITH SWEET POTATO FRIES.
BUT AFTER SHORT RIBS,
YOUR BASIC FOCACCIA BURGER
OR PANINI WITH SAUSAGE,
PEPPERS AND MOZZARELLA,
YOU GOTTA TOP OFF
WITH SOME DESSERT.
IT'S CALLED A BROWNIE SUNDAE,
AND IT'S VERY LARGE.
AND THE BROWNIE IS HOMEMADE.
IN FACT,
ALL OF THIS IS HOMEMADE
EVERY DAY FROM SCRATCH
IN THE BAKERY
IN THE BASEMENT.
SO, TEDDY,
I FEEL LIKE I'M DOWN HERE IN
LIKE AN ARTIST'S STUDIO.
OH, YEAH?
WHAT DO YOU MAKE DOWN HERE?
CHOCOLATE CAKES,
CARROT CAKE, CHEESECAKE,
BANANA CREAM PIES.
COCONUT CUSTARD, PECAN PIE,
APPLE, CHERRY, BLUEBERRY.
YOU KNOW, "APPLE, CHERRY,
BLUEBERRY."
I MEAN, EVERYBODY HAS THOSE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE BUY
THOSE THINGS, YOU GUYS.
NO, WE MAKE EVERYTHING.
A LOT OF PLACES BUY THEIR BREAD
IN ROLLS, TOO, BUT NOT HERE,
WHERE UNCLE TEDDY'S TURNING OUT
MORE THAN A DOZEN VARIETIES.
THIS IS FOCACCIA BREAD.
LOOK AT THAT WITH THE OLIVES
AND THE TOMATOES...
OLIVES AND FETA CHEESE
AND TOMATOES.
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WHAT IS THIS--
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
THIS IS FOR PANINI.
PANINI?
THAT ONE JUST CAME
OUT OF THE OVEN.
YEP.
NICE AND WARM.
MM-HMM.
THE PECANS AND THE...
CRANBERRIES.
PECANS, CRANBERRIES...
AND HONEY.
SMELLS GREAT.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF, BUDDY.
WHAT WAS THE PASSION
35 YEARS AGO TO START BAKING?
I MEAN, WHAT ARE WE DOING--
10, 12 DIFFERENT TYPES OF BREAD
AND 30 DIFFERENT TYPES
OF CAKES AND DESSERTS. WHY?
YOU DON'T WANT
TO HAVE EVERY DAY
THE SAME CAKE
AND THE SAME BREAD.
YOU LIKE TO HAVE
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
THAT'S WHY WE DO THAT.
SO YOU--TO TAKE CARE
OF YOUR CUSTOMERS,
TO DO SOMETHING DIFFERENT,
YOU KEEP EXPANDING.
OF COURSE.
I GOTTA TELL YOU--
THAT'S WHY WE'VE BEEN HERE
IN ONE PLACE FOR 35 YEARS,
ESPECIALLY IN THIS AREA.
AND THAT'S WHY
IT'S PACKED UPSTAIRS.
YEAH.
THAT'S WHY THERE'S
1,000 PEOPLE A DAY...
OF COURSE.
AND THAT'S WHY TOMMY,
COSTA AND ALEX
ARE LEARNING EVERYTHING
THEY CAN FROM UNCLE TEDDY.
WE WERE BROUGHT UP IN LIKE
A FAMILY ORIENTED RESTAURANT,
GREAT TUTORS
WITH OUR FATHERS.
(Alex) FAMILY COMES FIRST,
BUT BUSINESS
IS A PRETTY CLOSE SECOND.
AND THAT'S WHY
THE EVEREADY
IS STILL ROCKIN' IT
AS A LOCAL LEGEND.
(girl) DATE NIGHT.
DATE NIGHT. HE BRINGS YOU
TO THE EVEREADY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NO, I'M LIKING IT.
(boy) WE'RE A CHEAP DATE.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADING OUT FOR MORE.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
IT'S BEEN REALLY GREAT
TALKIN' TO YA.
THANKS A LOT.
I'LL BE HERE ALL WEEK.
YEAH, THANKS. PULL IT!