HI, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR SOME OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
AMERICAN CLASSICS.
WE'LL HEAD TO MICHIGAN...
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
WHERE A YOUNG COUPLE
NEW TO THE DINER BIZ
IS BRINGING A COLLECTION
OF CLASSICS BACK TO LIFE...
I LOVED THE PLACE.
I LOVED WHAT IT COULD BE.
TO CALIFORNIA TO A LOG CABIN
WITH A WHOLE NEW TAKE
ON BAR FOOD...
YOU HAVE GOT A LOT OF FLAVORS
GOING ON IN A LITTLE SPOT.
TO MINNEAPOLIS, WHERE
BREAKFAST IS OFF THE HOOK...
GOT A WAFFLE UP.
(woman)
IT'S NOT SPLIT.
DON'T SEND IT DOWN
UNTIL IT'S SPLIT.
NOT SPLIT.
DON'T SEND 'EM...
MAKE 'EM SPLIT IT
THEMSELVES.
...SPLIT IT
AT A PLACE THAT'S PROUD
TO BE A DIVE...
DO YOU REALLY CONSIDER
THIS PLACE A DIVE?
OF COURSE.
LOOK AT IT,
FOR CRYING OUT LOUD.
AND OVER TO ST. PAUL
FOR HOMEMADE ITALIAN
BROUGHT STRAIGHT TO YOUR CAR.
OH, I THINK IT'S A TRADITION
FOR A LOT OF FOLKS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
ROAD TRIPPIN' THROUGH
SOUTHWESTERN MICHIGAN,
THE LAST THING YOU'D
PROBABLY EXPECT TO FIND
WOULD BE A 50-
OR 60-YEAR-OLD DINER.
I MEAN, WE'RE NOT IN NEW JERSEY.
BUT TO FIND TWO OF 'EM OR THREE
OF 'EM SIDE BY SIDE BY SIDE--
COME ON.
(woman) ORDER IN.
THE LUCY CHICKEN.
DINERS WEREN'T
THAT COMMON OUT HERE.
SEE, THEY WERE
A NOVELTY TO US.
SO WHEN THIS CAME HERE,
WE HADN'T SEEN A DINER BEFORE,
YOU KNOW, UNLESS
YOU WENT OUT EAST.
BUT EVEN OUT EAST, NO ONE HAD
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE.
THIS IS DEFINITELY THE ONE PLACE
THAT YOU CAN FIND IT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN IT ANYWHERE ELSE.
SIDE-BY-SIDE ORIGINALS
WITH CLASSIC
HOMEMADE DINER FOOD
AND FRESH-BAKED PIES--
THE WAY IT USED TO BE,
LONG BEFORE THESE DINERS'
NEW OWNERS WERE EVEN BORN.
IT WAS OUR SOMEDAY--
SOMEDAY WE'LL DO THIS. SOMEDAY
THIS IS WHAT WE WANT TO DO.
AND WHEN WE GOT HERE,
WE JUST COULDN'T PASS IT UP.
YOU SEE, THE GUY WHO BROUGHT
THE DINERS IN WANTED OUT.
ARTIST JERRY BERTA
BOUGHT THE FIRST ONE
TO USE AS HIS STUDIO,
THEN THE OTHER TWO
TO RUN HIS RESTAURANTS.
THEN HE GOT FED UP
WITH THE FOOD BIZ.
I'M REAL COOL IN FRONT
OF THE COUNTER.
"HEY, HI, WELCOME TO ROSIE'S.
COME ON IN.
SIT DOWN. SIT DOWN. HOW YOU
DOING" AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
BUT BACK
OF THE COUNTER, MAN,
IT'S LIKE BEING A PRINCIPAL IN
A HIGH SCHOOL--IN A JUNIOR HIGH.
WHEN JERRY DECIDED TO SELL,
RANDY AND JONELLE ROEST
DECIDED THIS WAS A BETTER BET
THAN NURSING SCHOOL FOR HER
AND MANAGING
A CHAIN RESTAURANT FOR HIM.
GET THAT SWEET SAUCE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME
THAT, LIKE, THE DINER
TALKED TO YOU
OR ANYTHING, DID IT?
I--IT--I DON'T--
I LOVED THE PLACE.
I LOVED WHAT IT COULD BE.
WHEN I GOT HERE,
I WAS HOPING
THAT WE COULD
BRING IT BACK THERE.
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE,
THAT MEANT DINER COOKING
THE WAY IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE.
MACARONI AND CHEESE
WITH GRAVY.
IF I'M GONNA SERVE IT TO PEOPLE,
IT SHOULD BE HOMEMADE.
THAT WAS MY FIRST TASK.
THERE WAS A LOT TO DO
WHEN WE GOT HERE,
BUT I DIDN'T WANT ANYBODY
TO SEE THIS PLACE
OR TASTE THE FOOD UNDER MY NAME
UNTIL IT WAS
WHAT I WAS PROUD OF.
THERE'S A WHOLE
BOOK OF RECIPES--
VEGETABLE BEEF SOUP,
CLAM CHOWDER,
ROASTED
CAULIFLOWER SOUP.
A COUPLE OF 'EM ARE MINE.
A HANDFUL ARE MY MOM'S.
SO YOU BROUGHT
IN THE RESERVES.
YOU BROUGHT IN MOM
AND WHO ELSE?
GRANDMA.
MOM, GRANDMA, YOU.
...A COUPLE
GREAT AUNTS.
THIS IS MOM.
THIS IS GRANDMA.
THIS IS MY GRANDMOTHER'S
BEEF AND EGG NOODLE RECIPE
THAT MY DAD
HAS GROWN UP WITH.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
MAKING THIS DISH?
36 YEARS.
IT'S A CHUCK ROAST.
A CHUCK ROAST.
IT'S GOT THE RIGHT TEXTURE
THAT IT JUST FALLS APART
WHEN IT'S DONE.
(Guy) SO WE GOT A LITTLE
BIT OF SALT AND PEPPER,
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
(Jonelle)
AND THEN WE SEAR 'EM.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
SLOW-ROAST IT?
COAT ON THE BACK,
AND WE SLOW-ROAST IT
WITH A GRAVY WE MIX UP.
MUSHROOM SOUP,
ONION SOUP,
AND NOW WE'RE...
...AND SOME OTHER
SPICES ADDED.
AND SOME OTHER SPICES THAT
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME.
WE JUST SAUTé SOME
ONIONS UP AND ADD IT TO IT,
AND IT ALL
GOES IN THE OVEN.
OH, YOU CLAP
FOR HER. WOW.
OH, THAT--
THAT'S SOME GRAVY.
NOW I'M GONNA BE REAL
HONEST WITH YA.
I AM GONNA BE MAKING
THIS AT HOME.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU
FULL CREDIT,
BUT THAT'S GOING
HOME WITH ME.
THE NOODLES AND BEEF--
THAT'S THE BOMB, HUH?
THE MENU'S FILLED
WITH REAL-DEAL COMFORT FOOD...
SIMPLE AND CLASSIC.
LIKE SLOPPY JOES, MEAT LOAF
AND FRESH ROAST TURKEY.
WE SLOW-ROAST IT IN THE OVEN
AND THEN SLICE IT
AND USE IT FOR OUR HOT
SANDWICHES AND OUR DINNERS.
IT'S LIKE BIG CHUNKS OF TURKEY.
IT'S NOT LUNCH MEAT.
IT'S REAL POTATOES.
IT'S NOT WHIPPED UP.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND IF THAT'S
NOT ENOUGH FOR YA,
HOW ABOUT FRENCH TOAST MADE
FROM SOMETHING SWEET AS CAKE
CALLED COBBLESTONE BREAD.
IT'S HOMEMADE.
WE MAKE IT HERE.
IT'S FULL OF APPLES
AND WALNUTS
AND CINNAMON,
AND IT'S GOT ICING.
IT'S AWESOME.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S LIKE A CINNAMON
ROLL, FRENCH TOAST.
GOD, THAT'S THE BOMB.
AND IT ISN'T JUST
THE COBBLESTONE BREAD.
THEY'RE SCRATCH-BAKING
EVERYTHING HERE.
YOU ACTUALLY MAKE IT?
A PIE LADY NAMED JOAN
THAT HELPS ME BAKE HERE,
AND WE MAKE EVERYTHING FROM
SCRATCH--BISCUITS, PIE.
GOTTA GO BACK
TO THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
COCONUT CREAM, BANANA CREAM,
CHOCOLATE CREAM.
OH, A LOT
OF CREAM PIES?
YES.
THERE SHOULD BE LIKE A HUGE SIGN
OUT THERE ON THE FREEWAY
ON 14 MILE ROAD
THAT SAYS "WE MAKE
PIES AND BISCUITS,"
BECAUSE, I MEAN,
YOU DON'T FIND A LOT...
I WANT TO PUT
"EVERYTHING FOR REAL."
THAT'S WHAT I WANT
TO PUT ON A SIGN.
EVERYTHING FOR REAL.
THAT'S NOT
A BAD SLOGAN.
WE WERE DRIVING DOWN
THE STREET, AND WE SAW--
OH, THERE'S A DINER.
LET'S GO THERE.
IT LOOKS LIKE A HOME-SPUN DINER.
AND SURE ENOUGH,
WE CAME IN HERE,
AND IT'S GREAT FOOD,
GREAT ATMOSPHERE.
WE LOVE IT. WE'LL COME BACK.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT RANDY
AND JONELLE WANT TO HEAR.
THIS IS WHY WE LOVE
TO RUN A RESTAURANT.
BUT THEIR QUICK SUCCESS
HASN'T COME EASY.
THAT'S IT.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING NONSTOP,
NOT JUST RUNNING THE PLACE,
BUT LEARNING HOW.
I'M TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
TO DO WITH MY SERVERS HERE.
ONE AND TWO
ARE IN THE FRONT.
YOU'RE SET TO GO. YOU'RE
GOOD ON YOUR TWO, RIGHT?
YEP.
YOU GOT THE END ONE
ON BOTH ENDS?
IF SOMEONE WAS GONNA
GO BUY THEIR OWN DINER,
WHAT ADVICE WOULD
YOU HAVE FOR THEM?
MY ADVICE TO THEM
IS TO NOT PLAN ANYTHING, UM,
FOR NEXT WEEK, NEXT MONTH
OR THE NEXT FIVE YEARS.
SO IT MADE PERFECT SENSE,
'CAUSE ONE OVERWHELMING
CHALLENGE ISN'T ENOUGH,
THAT WITHIN A FEW MONTHS
OF REVAMPING ROSIE'S,
RANDY AND JONELLE REOPENED
THE UNUSED DINER NEXT DOOR
AS A FAMILY-FRIENDLY
SPORTS BAR.
THIS IS THE FIRST DAY,
BEING THE GRAND OPENING,
THAT WE'VE HAD THE TRAFFIC
IN BOTH PLACES.
SO IT'S A LEARNING
EXPERIENCE FOR NOW.
...BUT A QUICK ONE.
WITHIN DAYS,
THE SYSTEM HAD CLICKED.
(woman) TWO ROSIE BURGERS
RIGHT NOW.
AND IN LESS THAN SIX MONTHS,
JONELLE AND RANDY
HAD BROUGHT BACK NOT ONE,
BUT TWO AMERICAN CLASSICS.
IT'S GOOD FOOD, GOOD PEOPLE,
AND IT'S JUST GOOD TO KNOW
A LITTLE BIT OF YOUR HISTORY.
AND THEY'VE STARTED MAKING
PLANS FOR THEIR THIRD DINER--
TO BRING IT BACK
FROM AN ART STUDIO
TO AN ICE-CREAM PARLOR.
IN THE MEANTIME,
THEY DID TAKE ONE DAY
TO STOP AND CELEBRATE
THEIR SUCCESS--
A DAYLONG PARTY WITH MUSIC,
CLASSIC CARS
AND A PIE-EATING CONTEST,
FEATURING ROSIE'S
HOMEMADE CHOCOLATE CREAM.
(cheering)
THEN IT WAS BACK TO WORK...
I GOT 'EM. GO AHEAD.
A COUPLE OF 20-SOMETHINGS
BRINGING BACK THE BEST
OF 50-SOMETHING YEARS AGO.
WE WANT TO KEEP IT NOSTALGIC
WITHOUT GOING OVERBOARD
WITH THE CLICHé
KIND OF THINGS.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
EVERYTHING THAT WE'VE CREATED
AND MAKE IT BETTER.
...MAKE IT WORK
LIKE CLOCKWORK
AND KEEP IT SOMETHING
WE'RE PROUD OF.
IT'S SO MUCH FUN TO BE
A PART OF. IT'S JUST NEAT.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING OUT WEST
TO A PLACE WHERE I'VE BEEN
HANGING OUT FOR YEARS.
IT'S A LOG CABIN
IN THE WINE COUNTRY...
THAT'S A HOT WING.
WHERE THE HOT WINGS
ARE SMOKIN',
BUT SO'S THE TRI-TIP STEAK
AND THE AHI TUNA.
THIS IS NOT YOUR STANDARD
LOG CABIN COOKIN'.
I THINK I COULD PUT THIS
ON A FLIP-FLOP
AND IT WOULD
TASTE GOOD.
WE'VE ROLLED
INTO SOME OF AMERICA'S
BEST DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES
FROM THE EAST TO THE SOUTH
TO THE MIDWEST,
NOW MY STOMPIN' GROUNDS--
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA,
THE WINE COUNTRY.
IT'S A LOG CABIN KIT
THAT IS 45 YEARS OLD.
THE RUSSIAN RIVER PUB
HAS BEEN ONE OF MY FAVORITE
CALIFORNIA HANGOUTS
FOR THE LAST TEN YEARS.
YOU PROBABLY THINK
YOU'VE GOT IT PEGGED,
YOU KNOW, YOUR BASIC DIVE--
BAR, POOL TABLE, PINBALL,
PLENTY OF BEER.
IF YOU'RE HUNGRY--BURGERS
OR THEIR FAMOUS CHICKEN WINGS.
AIN'T NO THING
BUT A CHICKEN WING."
THAT'S A HOT WING.
BUT THEN THERE'S
THE REST OF THE MENU...
I THINK I COULD PUT THIS
ON A FLIP-FLOP
AND IT WOULD
TASTE GOOD.
SPECIALTIES LIKE BEEF TRI TIP
WITH CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND BLUE CHEESE,
FRESH HOMEMADE PESTO
ON GRILLED CHICKEN
AND ONLY IN A CALIFORNIA
DIVE BAR...
THAT'S LIKE
SUSHI-GRADE AHI, DUDE.
YOU HAVE GOT A LOT OF FLAVORS
GOING ON IN A LITTLE SPOT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M GONNA
GET PLOWED INTO ANY SECOND
AND END UP
IN THE FRYER.
BUT IT'S WORKING.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
LONG-TIME CUSTOMERS SAY THIS
PLACE HAS TURNED AMAZING
SINCE THE NEW OWNER TOOK OVER
A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO.
THIS IS AWESOME.
ISN'T THAT GREAT?
I WANT EVERYTHING THAT
COMES OUT OF MY KITCHEN--
I WANT TO BE
PROUD OF IT.
WENDY ILLG HAD BEEN A WAITRESS.
YOU WERE WORKING
IN RESTAURANTS.
YES, ABSOLUTELY.
I DID FOR ALMOST
TWO DECADES, ACTUALLY.
SHE CAME HERE ONE DAY
TO APPLY FOR A JOB
AND FOUND OUT THE OWNER
WANTED TO SELL.
I ALWAYS WANTED MY OWN PLACE,
AND IT WAS REALLY TIME.
FOR WENDY,
AFTER ALL THOSE YEARS
OF WORKING IN SOMEONE
ELSE'S RESTAURANT,
IT FEELS LIKE GETTING THIS
PLACE WAS ALWAYS MEANT TO BE.
MY FATHER HAS BEEN PASSED
AWAY FOR ABOUT 12 YEARS.
SO MY STEPMOTHER WALKED
THROUGH THE DOOR,
AND SHE GOES,
"OH, MY GOSH.
YOUR FATHER TRIED TO BUY
THIS PLACE 20 YEARS AGO."
THIS PLACE,
THE PUB? NO?
YES,
THIS EXACT PLACE,
WHICH, FOR ME, YOU KNOW,
WHEN I FIRST CAME HERE,
I JUST--
I FELT THE LOVE.
I WALKED IN THE DOOR.
I FELT THE WARMTH.
I SAW THE DIAMOND
IN THE ROUGH,
AND I JUST--
I LOVED IT HERE.
A LOT OF THIS IS HISTORY
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE.
SHE WANTS TO KEEP
THE SOUL OF A DIVE,
WHERE SIGNING THE WALLS
JUST SEEMS TO MAKE SENSE.
PEOPLE COME IN,
AND THEY SAY,
"OH, I REMEMBER WHEN WE ALL
WROTE OUR NAMES ON THE WALL."
FAST FREDDY
RIGHT OVER HERE.
BUT SHE ALSO WANTS IT
TO BE A PLACE
THAT'S COMFORTABLE
FOR EVERYONE.
SINCE WENDY TOOK IT OVER,
I CAN BRING MY KIDS HERE.
THEY CAN HANG OUT.
(woman) THE KIDS PLAY POOL.
THERE'S VIDEO GAMES.
THEY LOVE IT HERE.
NO, TOTALLY.
IT'S A GOOD THING FOR
THE GIRLS TO GET AWAY, TOO.
IN FACT, ASK WENDY
WHAT SHE'S PROUDEST OF...
IT'S SAFE. COME ON IN.
AND SHE'LL SHOW YOU
THE LADIES ROOM.
YOU WOULD BE SURPRISED AT HOW
IMPORTANT THAT IS TO A LADY
WHEN SHE'S OUT AT PLACE
KNOWN AS A DIVE BAR
THAT THE BATHROOM BE SOMEWHERE
SHE FEELS COMFORTABLE AND SAFE.
AND THE WHOLE COMFORTABLE,
RELAXED THING--
IT'S GOING ON
IN THE KITCHEN, TOO.
RECIPES? WHAT RECIPES?
THIS IS EYEBALL
RECIPE?
YEAH,
WE GOT IT DOWN.
EVERYBODY HAS
A GOOD EYEBALL.
SOME PEOPLE HAVE TWO.
TWO.
FOR COOK BRENDA WEDDLE,
BAR FOOD DOESN'T
HAVE TO BE BAR FOOD,
LIKE HER OFF-THE-HOOK TRI TIP.
IT'S BEEN
IN A BRINE OVERNIGHT.
I'VE GOT SOME
ROASTING RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE DOWN
HERE WORKING?
IT'S GOT SOME PARSLEY, ONION,
GARLIC, WORCESTERSHIRE.
WOW.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SLICE IT,
FLASH IT ON THE GRILL,
MELT THE BLUE CHEESE ON TOP
WITH THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
OH, THAT'S
EXCELLENT.
ANOTHER EXCUSE
TO TRY IT AGAIN.
WE'RE HAVING SLOW-ROASTED
BARBECUE PORK TODAY.
BONELESS PORK BUTT?
BONELESS PORK BUTT.
ALL RIGHT,
BEER IS HERE.
ADD THAT
TO THE PORK.
OKAY. SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH SOME ONIONS.
I'M GONNA GRAB
SOME CARROTS.
WE GONNA THROW SOME
GARLIC IN THAT PORK ALSO?
WE ARE GONNA THROW SOME
GARLIC IN THAT PORK.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
CRACKED PEPPER
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF KOSHER SALT,
'CAUSE WE'RE GONNA FINISH
COOKING IT IN THE BARBECUE SAUCE
IN THE OVEN.
IT'S SERVED WITH HOMEMADE
GARLIC MASHED POTATOES,
AND SHE'S MAKING A KILLER
SPLIT PEA AND HAM SOUP.
WHAT ARE ALL
THE INGREDIENTS?
JUST SPLIT PEAS
AND WATER.
THROW IN
THE HAM HOCKS,
AND THEN I'M GONNA SAUTé UP
THE VEGETABLES AND ADD THOSE--
CARROTS, CELERY,
ONION, GARLIC.
AND YOU'RE NOT
GONNA PURéE THAT?
YOU'RE GONNA LET THAT
HAVE CHUNKS AND...
A LITTLE CHUNKY.
AT THE END WHEN
WE ADD THE MINT,
IT CHANGES
THE WHOLE FLAVOR.
MINT'S GONNA
GO IN THIS?
FRESH MINT.
OHH.
AND THERE'S AN AHI TUNA SALAD
WITH A HOMEMADE DRESSING
BUILT AROUND RED WINE VINEGAR
AND A FLAVOR-RICH SOY SAUCE
CALLED SHOW SHOYU.
GARLIC GOING IN?
YOU'RE GONNA ADD
THE GARLIC, GINGER.
YOU GOT THE GREEN ONION
IN THERE.
THE AHI TUNA IS QUICK-SEARED
WITH TOASTED SESAME SEEDS,
SALT AND BLACK PEPPER.
MMM.
EVEN THEIR BURGERS
ARE SOMETHING SPECIAL.
PEOPLE ARE LIKE, "WOW,
THAT'S WAY TOO HARD, WENDY.
THERE'S TOO MANY INGREDIENTS
IN THE MEXI BURGER."
AND IT'S TRUE,
BUT PEOPLE LOVE IT,
AND MY GUYS
CAN HANDLE IT,
AND WE PUT OUT PLATES
THAT WE'RE ALL PROUD OF.
MORE THAN BURGERS, FOR WENDY,
IT'S ABOUT MAKING
EVERYTHING JUST RIGHT,
BRINGING BACK
THE TRUE AMERICAN CLASSIC
HER FATHER FELL IN LOVE WITH
MORE THAN 20 YEARS AGO.
MYSELF AND OUR FRIENDS HAVE
BEEN ON THE FLOOR, YOU KNOW,
SCRUBBING OR CLEANING
OR WHATEVER IT IS
TO MAKE
THIS PLACE WORK,
AND I REALLY, YOU KNOW,
I LOOK UP
AT MY DAD'S PICTURE
ON THE WALL,
AND I SAY,
"WE'RE MAKING IT."
NEXT WE'RE HEADED
TO A LEGENDARY BREAKFAST SPOT
THAT GOT ONE OF THE WORLD'S
MOST PRESTIGIOUS
CULINARY AWARDS,
EVEN THOUGH THE OWNER
CALLS THE PLACE A DUMP.
WE'RE SORT OF A DUMP
ASPIRING TO BE A DIVE.
BUT JUST WAIT
TILL YOU TASTE THE FOOD.
IT'S THE BEST EGGS, BECAUSE HE
MAKES IT WITH CREAM AND BUTTER.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
ABOUT CLASSIC AMERICAN DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES
IS YOU REALLY CAN'T JUDGE
A BOOK BY ITS COVER,
LIKE THIS BREAKFAST JOINT
IN MINNEAPOLIS--
WOULD YOU BELIEVE A JAMES BEARD
AWARD WINNER?
THIS IS A DIVE.
EVERYBODY ELSE MOVE
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
WE GOT A WAFFLE UP.
GOT A WAFFLE UP.
(woman)
IT'S NOT SPLIT.
DON'T SEND IT DOWN
UNTIL IT'S SPLIT.
NOT SPLIT.
DON'T SEND IT--
MAKE 'EM SPLIT IT
THEMSELVES.
...SPLIT IT
DO YOU REALLY CONSIDER
THIS PLACE A DIVE?
OF COURSE. LOOK AT IT,
FOR CRYING OUT LOUD.
AND OWNER DOUG GRINA IS DOING
ALL HE CAN TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
I NEED ANOTHER
HOLLANDAISE.
(woman)
NO, YOU DON'T.
BUT THEN THERE'S THE FOOD...
BEST BREAKFAST IN TOWN.
BEAUTIFUL OMELETS, EGGS
BENEDICT WITH REAL HOLLANDAISE,
FLUFFY SCRAMBLED EGGS
WITH CHEDDAR CHEESE,
MUSHROOM AND GARLIC.
AND IT'S THE BEST EGGS,
BECAUSE HE MAKES IT
WITH CREAM AND BUTTER.
EVERYTHING'S MADE FRESH
AND TO ORDER--
TWO KINDS OF HOMEMADE
PANCAKE BATTER--
BUTTERMILK AND WHOLE WHEAT
WITH HONEY.
AND RECIPES ARE NOT
NEARLY AS IMPORTANT
AS BEING ABLE
TO FEEL YOUR BATTER
AND KNOW WHAT'S
HAPPENING WITH IT.
SOMETIMES I HAVE TO ADD FLOUR.
SOMETIMES I HAVE
TO ADD BUTTERMILK.
IT'S NEVER
EXACTLY THE SAME.
WE MAKE OUR OWN
CORN BEEF HASH.
I LOVE
YOU WANT THAT?
THAT'S
GOOD-LOOKING HASH.
WOW. THAT HASH
IS MONEY, MAN.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S IN IT?
ONIONS, GARLIC,
GREEN PEPPER,
PARSLEY, JUST A TINY
HINT OF HORSERADISH.
THIS MIGHT BE A DIVE,
BUT YOU REALLY...
I LOVE FOOD.
I GO HOME FROM HERE,
I STOP AT THE GROCERY STORE,
SEE WHAT LOOKS GOOD
AND PLAN A DINNER.
AND AS FOR THAT DIVE THING...
WE'RE SORT OF A DUMP
ASPIRING TO BE A DIVE.
MAYBE, BUT IN 2004,
THIS PLACE ACTUALLY
RECEIVED A JAMES BEARD AWARD
AS AN AMERICAN CLASSIC.
I HAVEN'T WORN THIS SINCE
I TRIED TO GO THROUGH SECURITY.
YOU KNOW,
THE JAMES BEARD AWARD--
THAT DOES HELP FROM
THE DUMP TO THE DIVE.
THAT'S A HELP.
AND THIS IS YOUR
BUSINESS PARTNER?
YES, THAT'S MY PARTNER
JAMES BRANDIS.
LOOK AT YOU GUYS.
YOU GUYS LOOK LIKE A COUPLE
HOLLYWOOD PRODUCERS.
AND IT ALL STARTED
WITH THE COMMITMENT TO MAKE
EVERYTHING OURSELVES,
WHICH STARTED WITH AL,
AND WE CONTINUED.
SO WHO WAS AL?
AL'S A TERRIFIC
GENTLEMAN
WHO STARTED
THIS PLACE IN 1950.
HE RETIRED IN '74.
DOUG'S BEEN HERE SINCE '79,
AND THE SETUP HASN'T
CHANGED IN YEARS--
GRILL UP FRONT...
GOT HALF AN EGGS BENE
AND A WHOOSIE AND A WHAT.
OMELETS AND SCRAMBLES IN BACK
BY THE WATER HEATER.
I NEED A 3-EGG HUEVOS
ON AN OVAL!
(woman) WHAT?
3-EGG HUEVOS
ON AN OVAL.
I'M GONNA GET YOU--
RADIO SHACK--20 BUCKS--
INTERCOM SYSTEM--
MONEY.
WHAT DO I NEED
THAT FOR?!
AND SOMEHOW THEY REALLY
DO TURN OUT SOME GREAT FOOD.
THE SPRING SPECIAL.
SPRING--THAT WAS BECAUSE WE
GOT ASPARAGUS IN THE SPRING.
THAT WAS BEFORE NAFTA.
NOW YOU CAN GET ASPARAGUS
EVERY TIME YOU WANT IT.
SO THEN YOU HAVE
THE SUMMER SPECIAL
WITH BASIL
AND MOZZARELLA...
YEAH.
AND THEN THE WINTER
SPECIAL.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY THERE
WERE NAMED WHAT--THE--
AFTER THAT, THE NAMING PROCESS
BECAME SOMEWHAT OBSCURE.
...WHICH MEANS FEEL FREE TO
ORDER THE WINTER IN THE SPRING.
WELL, IT'S WINTER SOMEWHERE.
TELL ME
ABOUT THE JOSE.
THE JOSE WAS NAMED AFTER A GUY
WHO USED TO EAT IN HERE...
HIS NAME WAS GEORGE?
HIS NAME WAS JOSE.
GET OUT.
NO, I'M NOT
KIDDING YA.
WHAT'S IN A JOSE?
TWO POACHED EGGS, SALSA
AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
PUT DOWN TWO HASH BROWNS.
POUR SOME OIL ON 'EM--
ON THE POTATOES.
YEAH, NOTHING LIKE
A LITTLE CHOLESTEROL.
THAT'S NOT CHOLESTEROL.
THAT'S SOY BEAN OIL.
SOY BEAN OIL?
SOY BEAN OIL.
I LIKE IT.
THERE YOU GO.
I BLEW THAT.
NO, NO,
THIS IS THE BEAUTY.
THIS IS WHERE
THE MAGIC HAPPENS.
THIS IS THE BEAUTY.
THIS IS THE MAGIC.
SEE, THEY DON'T
KNOW THIS PART.
THE GUYS ARE RIGHT BEHIND US,
BUT THAT DOESN'T MATTER.
THAT DOESN'T MATTER.
OKAY, THEN
THE CHEDDAR CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT. YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH THIS COSTS?
IT'S 12 BUCKS EACH.
NO, GET OUT OF HERE.
$6.70.
COME ON, DUDE. I MEAN,
FIVE AND A QUARTER?
YEAH.
GET 7, 8 BUCKS
OUT OF THESE TWO.
THE PRICE
JUST WENT UP.
THEY'RE STUDENTS.
DOUG SAYS HE DOESN'T LIKE
TO RAISE PRICES.
OF COURSE, HE DOESN'T LIKE
TO PAINT THE PLACE EITHER
OR THROW ANYTHING OUT
OR CHANGE MUCH OF ANYTHING.
NO CREDIT CARDS HERE.
INSTEAD, THEY'VE GOT
PAYMENT BOOKS.
BOOKS BACK
FROM THE '60s.
HERE'S HOW IT WORKS.
YOU PUT SOME CASH
ON YOUR ACCOUNT...
HEY, DOUG,
DO YOU TAKE CHECKS?
(Doug) YEAH,
BUT NOT ANY BAD ONES.
IT SAYS HERE THAT YOU STARTED
WITH $41.43 FROM YOUR OLD BOOK.
AND THEY KEEP TRACK
AS YOU EAT BACKWARDS TO ZERO.
YOU EAT THE SAME THING
EVERY TIME, DON'T YA?
JUST ABOUT.
'CAUSE IT'S
$4.81, $4.81.
OH, HERE'S MAGGIE
WITH SOME FRIENDS--$19.50.
THAT'S OKAY?
THAT'S OKAY, YEAH.
IS IT COOL IF I PUT
MY BREAKFAST ON HERE?
OH, YEAH.
WHERE ELSE DO YOU
EAT BREAKFAST?
THIS IS
THE ONLY PLACE.
THE ONLY PLACE?
HOW ABOUT YOU?
ACTUALLY, YEAH,
THE ONLY PLACE.
I MAKE IT AT HOME,
OR I COME HERE.
...TO A DIVE...
EVERYBODY ELSE MOVE
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
COVERED OVER A FORMER ALLEY
BETWEEN TWO OTHER BUILDINGS,
WHERE THE CROWD BACKS UP
WAITING FOR A SEAT...
I GOT A STACK AND SAUSAGE UP.
AND A SELF-TRAINED COOK
KEEPS A TRADITION ALIVE,
AT LEAST UNTIL CLOSING TIME.
WHAT TIME ARE YOU GUYS
GONNA CLOSE TODAY?
1:00 P.M.
SOMEBODY PICK UP
THESE PANCAKES!
WHEN WE COME BACK...
NO ONE ELSE GETS TAUGHT
HOW TO MAKE THIS, HUH?
(woman) NO.
AFTER BREAKFAST AT AL'S,
YOU CAN HOP ACROSS TOWN
FOR SOME AUTHENTIC ITALIAN
FOOD AT A CLASSIC DRIVE-IN.
I JUST WANTED TO SEE
IF YOU GUYS ARE THERE.
AFTER MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY,
THE DARI-ETTE DRIVE-IN
IN ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA,
IS AS CLASSIC AS THEY COME.
THEY'VE STILL GOT CARHOPS,
SPEAKER BOXES...
JUST WANTED TO SEE
IF YOU GUYS ARE THERE.
AND MEALS ON A TRAY.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
VERY GOOD.
EXCELLENT.
IT ALWAYS IS.
BUT GET A LOAD
OF WHAT'S ON THAT TRAY.
MOST OF THE ITALIAN FOOD
UP HERE IN MINNESOTA,
I DON'T KNOW, IT MUST BE MADE
BY SWEDES OR SOMETHING,
SO THIS PLACE
IS JUST A TREASURE.
WE WANTED TO SHARE WHAT
WE GREW UP WITH, YOU KNOW?
WE GREW UP WITH THE BIG ITALIAN
DINNERS AND ALL THAT,
AND WE WANTED
TO SHARE THAT.
ANGELA FIDA'S BEEN AT
THE DARI-ETTE HER ENTIRE LIFE.
I LOVE WHAT I DO.
IT'S IN ME.
IT'S WHAT
I WAS BORN TO DO.
NOW HOW LONG'S
IT BEEN OPEN?
55 YEARS.
HER GRANDPARENTS
GOT IT STARTED.
HER PARENTS KEPT IT GOING,
AND NOW SHE'S CARRYING ON
THE TRADITION.
AND PEOPLE HAVE
JUST BEEN COMING BACK
GENERATION
AFTER GENERATION.
THAT'S RIGHT.
...FOR EVERYTHING FROM ITALIAN
COLD CUT SANDWICHES
TO HOMEMADE MEATBALLS
AND SAUSAGE,
ALL KINDS OF PASTA
AND HOMEMADE SAUCE
FROM A FAMILY-ONLY RECIPE.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
GIVE IT TO ME.
UH, NO.
OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, ONIONS,
A LITTLE BASIL,
A LITTLE OREGANO.
WHAT ELSE AM I GETTING IN THERE?
A LITTLE ITALIAN PARSLEY?
JUST A LITTLE LOVE,
THAT'S ALL.
JUST A LITTLE LOVE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GIVE ME ANYTHING ELSE?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
YOU'RE JUST
LEAVING ME AT THAT?
LIKE THAT?
OKAY, VERY NICE.
THERE YOU GO.
THIS IS GONNA COOK FOR HOW
LONG? WE GOTTA STIR THIS?
RIGHT, ABOUT SEVEN
AND A HALF, EIGHT HOURS.
SO NO ONE ELSE GETS TAUGHT
HOW TO MAKE THIS, HUH?
NO.
I LET 'EM STIR ONCE
IN A WHILE, BUT THAT'S IT.
WOW.
SHE'LL ALSO LET 'EM MAKE
MEATBALLS AND ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
AND WHAT'S OUR MIX
IN HERE?
PORK...
PORK.
SOME SEASONING...
SOME SEASONING.
AND OBVIOUSLY
A TOUCH OF LOVE.
AND LOVE.
YEAH, I--AND LOVE.
BUT YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT SHE DOES TO 'EM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
IN THE FRYER.
RIGHT.
IN THE FRYER?
IT MAKES A HUGE TREMENDOUS
DIFFERENCE ON THE FLAVOR.
I LIKE THE CRUNCHY
OUTSIDE.
OKAY, SO NOW WE JUST
START SLIDING 'EM IN?
RIGHT.
MMM, MAN.
YOU CAN GET THE MEATBALLS
ON PASTA OR IN A SANDWICH.
AND THERE'S THIS
SAUSAGE SANDWICH
WITH MOZZARELLA AND SAUCE
CALLED THE ITALIANO.
IT'S ANGELA'S BIGGEST SELLER...
IT'S TERRIFIC.
DELIVERED TO YOUR CAR
JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
OH, I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 36 YEARS.
NO?
YES.
REALLY?
OH, I THINK IT'S A TRADITION
FOR A LOT OF FOLKS
AND A LOT OF FAMILIES.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
AND JUST DON'T GET CAUGHT ON
CAMERA GRABBING YOUR LUNCH HERE
WITHOUT TELLING YOUR FAMILY
YOU'RE COMING.
YOU SHOULD PROBABLY
CALL HIM AT HOME
AND SEE IF YOU CAN TAKE
SOME BACK TO HIM.
I'M NOT GONNA
TELL HIM.
HE'LL KNOW.
HE'LL SMELL MY BREATH,
AND HE'LL SAY,
"YOU'VE BEEN THERE."
BY THE WAY,
THIS CARHOPPING THING--
WHEN I SIGNED ON, NOBODY
MENTIONED TRASH PATROL...
THEY DIDN'T PUSH THE BUTTON.
OR A DRESS CODE.
YOU GOTTA TUCK
YOUR SHIRT IN.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK NICE
FOR THE CUSTOMERS.
BUT IT'S ALL PART
OF ANGELA'S COMMITMENT
TO DOING THINGS JUST RIGHT,
THE WAY THEY'VE BEEN DOING 'EM
FOR OVER HALF A CENTURY.
IT WAS INSTILLED
IN MY FROM MY PARENTS
FROM BEING BORN AND RAISED
IN THIS BUSINESS.
SO WHEN THEY WERE DOING IT,
THIS IS HOW THEY WERE DOING IT?
RIGHT.
GRANDFATHER DID
THE SAME THING?
RIGHT. IF IT'S NOT
BROKE, DON'T FIX IT.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS WE GOTTA HIT.
WE'LL SEE YA NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO WHEN YOU WERE DOING TIME,
YOU WERE ACTUALLY...