HI, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR SOME
OF AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
SOME AMERICAN CLASSICS--
ONE-OF-A-KIND PLACES DOING
GREAT FOOD THEIR OWN WAY--
THE TEXAS SHACK
WITH THE GOURMET CHEF...
WOW.
WHERE YOU WON'T BELIEVE
WHAT THE BURGERS ARE MADE OF,
THE KANSAS DINER
THAT'S LIKE A SECRET CLUB...
WE HAVE HAMBURGER JIM,
BLUES JIM, BICYCLE JIM.
YOU JUST GOTTA BREAK THE CODE.
I NEED A BEAT 17 OVER
ON SNAGGLEPUSS' BICYCLE TABLE.
AND GREAT GREEK FOOD
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DESERT.
WHAT'S THIS DOING HERE?
WHEN I CAME HERE, I WAS BROKE,
AND YOU START
DOING YOUR OWN THING.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN TARPLEY, TEXAS,
WHICH IS ABOUT AN HOUR WEST
OF SAN ANTONIO.
NOW THEY GOT ABOUT 50 PEOPLE
BETWEEN SIGNS, AS THEY SAY,
AND THEY GOT A POST OFFICE,
A GENERAL STORE
AND A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT CALLED
MAC & ERNIE'S ROADSIDE EATERY.
I THINK
IT'S A SHACK.
SHACK--OKAY, SO WE'RE
GONNA GO WITH SHACK.
IT'S A SHACK, ALL RIGHT,
NEXT TO A CREEK
DEEP IN THE TEXAS HILL COUNTRY,
WHERE SELF-TAUGHT CHEF
NAYLENE DILLINGHAM...
ANY FORMAL
CULINARY TRAINING?
NO.
IS CRANKING OUT
TOTALLY ROCKIN' FOOD
IN AN OPEN-AIR KITCHEN.
WHAT DO YOU DO WHEN
IT RAINS--STAY OUT OF IT?
UH, SPEAK LOUDER.
YOU HAVE TO SPEAK LOUDER.
TIN ROOF IS KIND
OF CLICKY-CLICKY?
HAVE YOU EVER THOUGHT
OF MAYBE GETTING TO--
YOU KNOW, I COULD TALK TO
THE PEOPLE AT THE GENERAL STORE,
MAYBE BUY THEM OUT...
NO.
MOVE INDOORS.
NO, IT WOULD CHANGE
ALL OF THE BEAUTY.
I THINK THE FLAVOR
WOULD CHANGE.
THE FLAVOR.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
AND THE FLAVOR'S
RIGHT ON POINT.
WHO WOULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT
TO FRY A LAMB CHOP?
IT'S NEW ZEALAND LAMB
COUNTRY-FRIED TEXAS-STYLE...
IT'S SO MOIST, SO JUICY.
LOCAL QUAIL
IN AN ANCHO CHILI SAUCE...
TENDER, WONDERFUL, JUICY.
TUNA IN GINGER BUTTER.
IT'S JUST--
IT'S PERFECT.
BUT THE DISH NAYLENE STARTED
WITH WAS THIS ONE--
THE CABRITO BURGER.
THE BURGER
IS WONDERFUL.
AND IF YOU DON'T SPEAK SPANISH,
CABRITO MEANS GOAT.
YOU HEARD ME--GOAT.
IT'S 100% GROUND CABRITO,
AND I RAISE THE GOATS.
NAYLENE, HER HUSBAND
AND ANOTHER COUPLE
NEEDED A MARKET
FOR THEIR GOATS.
THE RESULT--THIS RESTAURANT
IN A SHACK AND THIS BURGER.
I CALL 'EM
CABRITO BURGERS,
BECAUSE IF YOU SAY
GOAT BURGER,
IT DOESN'T
HAVE THE SAME--
IT DOESN'T--
MUSKY, YEAH.
I WANTED TO CALL IT
A McMUTTON,
BUT WE KNOW WHO WOULD
SUE ME OVER THAT.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO COOK ONE?
YEAH. I WANT
TO MAKE ONE, THOUGH.
WELL, NO, I CAN'T
LET YOU DO THAT.
WHY?
BECAUSE I WON'T TELL YOU
WHAT'S IN IT.
I SMELL GARLIC.
I CAN SEE THAT THAT IS EITHER
PARSLEY OR CILANTRO.
I CAN'T REALLY
GET THE NOSE OF IT.
(whispering)
TELL ME THE RECIPE.
NO.
(normal voice) WHERE'D
THE RECIPE COME FROM?
MY HEAD.
YOU GO TO THE HOT SPOT
WITH IT--8 OUNCES.
WOW, THAT'S NOT GONNA
BE BAD AT ALL.
WHAT DO YOU
SERVE THAT ON?
ON A KAISER ROLL
WITH SOME
PEPPER JACK CHEESE.
YOU WANNA GET
THE PEPPER JACK CHEESE?
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A LITTLE
MORSEL OF DELIGHT.
WOW,
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
THANK YOU.
WOW.
YOU CAN ENJOY THAT BURGER IN
THE PARKING LOT DINING ROOM...
THAT'S WHAT I CALL
THE VERANDA.
RIGHT BEHIND THE GENERAL STORE.
WHEN YOU SIT DOWN,
DO YOU JUST PICK A BENCH
AND THEN OTHER PEOPLE
JUST SIT DOWN?
THAT'S
THE NEAT THING
IS YOU MEET PEOPLE,
AND YOU NEVER KNOW WHO
YOU'RE GONNA SIT WITH.
OH, YOU DON'T KNOW
EACH OTHER YET?
NO, WE JUST MET.
BUT THEY'RE ALL HERE
FOR THE SAME REASON.
EVERYTHING'S
SO FANTASTIC.
YOU SEE,
AFTER THE BURGERS TOOK OFF,
NAYLENE STARTED
EXPANDING THE MENU.
MEDIUM-WELL.
I GOTTA STAY ON IT.
NOW SHE'S KEEPING
A SMALL STAFF CRANKIN'.
(Naylene) HOLD ON, SHAUNTAY.
WHILE SHE'S COOKIN' OUT BACK...
TURN THE NEXT TICKET, PLEASE.
THEY'RE DOING
EVERYTHING ELSE UP FRONT
IN CRAMPED QUARTERS WITH ALL
THE CONVENIENCE OF A DORM ROOM.
THAT'S A SHELF.
(Naylene) IT IS.
I FEEL LIKE
I'M IN COLLEGE.
IT'S KIND
OF RECYCLING.
WE'RE ON THE, YOU KNOW,
ECOLOGICAL THING.
DOES IT ALWAYS
START LIKE THIS
WHEN YOU OPEN
AT 5:00--
IT'S JUST--I MEAN,
THERE'S A LINE?
CHICKEN-FRIED
LAMB CHOP.
(Naylene) THERE
USUALLY IS A LINE.
WOW, ANOTHER LAMB,
ANOTHER LAMB,
CABRITO BURGER,
A LAMB, A RIB EYE,
A SMALL FISH
AND A LAMB.
LAMB'S POPULAR TODAY.
DOWN THOSE GO.
MAYBE IT WAS AN ACCIDENT--
MAYBE SHE DROPPED A LAMB CHOP
INTO THE CHICKEN-
FRIED-STEAK BATTER.
I HEARD THAT A FRIEND'S DAD
USED TO LOVE THESE LAMB CHOPS,
AND YOU THOUGHT,
WELL, I'LL GO AHEAD AND--
SHE SAID, "YOU ALWAYS
HAVE LAMB ON THE MENU,
DON'T YOU, NAYLENE?"
AND I SAID,
"YOU BET."
SHE SAYS,
"MAN, I MISS IT.
DADDY USED TO ALWAYS MAKE
CHICKEN-FRIED LAMB CHOPS."
AND IT WAS LIKE A LIGHTBULB
THAT WENT OFF IN MY LITTLE HEAD,
AND I SAID, "LAMB CHOPS--
CHICKEN-FRIED LAMB CHOPS?"
LAMB CHOPS--
I'M TELLIN' YA.
AND ROLL 'EM AROUND
IN THE FLOUR.
A LITTLE
SEASONED FLOUR.
AND THIS IS SOME
BUTTERMILK.
OKAY,
DREDGED 'EM ONCE,
POPPED 'EM
INTO THE BUTTERMILK
AND THEN
BACK IN AGAIN.
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
THEY'LL DEEP-FRY ABOUT THREE
MINUTES TO MEDIUM-RARE.
AND TO GO WITH 'EM, THERE'S
A HOMEMADE DARK-ROUX GRAVY
FROM NAYLENE'S MOTHER'S RECIPE.
YOU GOT OIL,
AND YOU GOT FLOUR.
MM-HMM.
I'VE GOT SOME
SALT AND PEPPER...
AND THEN YOU'VE
GOT SALT AND PEPPER.
AND THE SECRET
INGREDIENT.
SECRET INGREDIENT--
CAN I SEE IT?
SURE.
SECRET INGREDIENT.
CAN I TASTE IT?
OF COURSE.
TURBINADO SUGAR.
YES.
VERY NICE.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'RE THERE.
OKAY, GAME ON.
MMM. THAT MIGHT BE THE BEST
LAMB CHOP I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU'RE GOING?
WHAT YOU GET IN THE PARKING LOT
DEPENDS ON WHAT NAYLENE
FEELS LIKE COOKING
THE DAY YOU SHOW UP.
THERE MIGHT BE SALMON OR LOCAL
QUAIL AND ANCHO CHILI SAUCE.
THIS IS AN ANCHO CHILI
THAT'S DRIED.
I JUST TAKE
THE SEEDS OUT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME HONEY,
TWO CLOVES OF GARLIC.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE LID
ON THIS BAD BOY?
IT GOT MISPLACED.
I SWEAR I'M LOSING MY HEARING
FROM THIS THING?
HUH?
OH-OH-OH.
AND YOU JUST TRY TO GET AS MUCH
GLAZE ON THERE THAT YOU CAN?
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND I LIKE TO CRISP IT UP
REALLY GOOD ON THE GRILL.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU'RE THINKIN'.
OOH, THAT IS JUICY.
MM-HMM.
FRESH DEFINITELY MAKES
A DIFFERENCE ON THESE.
YEAH, I FEEL LIKE I'M HAVING
A LITTLE PRETEND MEAL.
WOW, THAT IS GOOD.
THAT'S VERY--I MEAN,
THEY LOOK SMALL,
BUT THEY'RE
VERY RICH...
THEY ARE VERY RICH.
AND VERY FILLING.
THAT'S EXCELLENT.
BUT YOU STILL GOTTA GRAB
A PIECE OF DESSERT--
ANYBODY'S.
SUSIE, SUSIE...
DON'T YELL.
SUSIE, HE'S
STEALING YOUR PIE.
GUY, DO YOU KNOW
WHAT WE DO?
WE CALL
ON THE TELEPHONE,
AND WE MAKE RESERVATIONS
FOR A PIECE OF PIE.
DO YOU SERIOUSLY?
YOU HAVE TO...
YEAH, YOU HAVE TO.
OTHERWISE YOU DON'T
GET ANY PIE.
OR YOU DON'T GET ONE.
OH, YOU HAVE TO LOCK IN
ON YOUR PIE?
YOU HAVE TO LOCK IN
ON THE PIE.
NOW HOW MANY MEALS DO YOU
SERVE ON AN AVERAGE DAY?
FRIDAY NIGHT
WE SERVED 145.
NO?
MM-HMM. LAST NIGHT--
130, 135. I'M NOT SURE.
IN A PARKING LOT
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE...
I LOVE IT.
AND THE TABLES ARE JAMMED.
WELL, I WAS HERE
FRIDAY...
WERE YOU HERE FRIDAY?
AND LAST SATURDAY AND
THE SATURDAY BEFORE THAT.
'CAUSE INSIDE THE SHACK,
THIS LADY CAN COOK.
(Naylene) AND THE FELLA
BEHIND HIM WAS LIKE,
"WHAT DO YOU MEAN, YOU GOT
THE LAST TWO ORDERS?
THAT'S NOT RIGHT."
HE OFFERED
TO BUY 'EM FROM HIM.
HE WAS SCALPING--HE WAS
SCALPING THE CHICK--
THE CHICKEN-FRIED
LAMB CHOPS?
MAKES SENSE TO ME.
I'VE HAD EIGHT SO FAR.
(Naylene)
(laughing)
WE SHOULD GIVE YOU
AN AWARD.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE AT A KANSAS CLASSIC
TO WHIP IT, FLIP IT...
(man) YOUR EGGS
ARE GONNA NEED A HELMET.
AND TALK SOME TRASH.
I NEED A BEAT 17 OVER
ON SNAGGLEPUSS' BICYCLE TABLE.
I'M UP EARLY IN WICHITA, KANSAS,
DOING WHAT ELSE, BUT LOOKING
FOR A GOOD DINER BREAKFAST.
SO YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE
WHERE I FOUND THIS PLACE.
TUCKED BEHIND THIS--
A BAKERY OUTLET--
AND AN AUTO PARTS STORE
IS BRINTS DINER,
WHERE THEY KNOW WHAT THEY'RE
DOING WITH A PLATEFUL OF EGGS.
OKAY, WE GOT A DENVER.
THE EGG MASTER
IS JESSIE MEDINA...
(Jessie) WHAT DO I GOT NEXT?
WHO'S BEEN COOKING
SINCE HE WAS 15...
OVER MEDIUM, BACON,
HASH BROWNS, WHOLE WHEAT.
AND FINALLY GOT A CHANCE
TO TAKE OVER THIS PLACE
JUST THREE YEARS AGO.
YOU ALWAYS WANTED
TO OWN YOUR OWN PLACE.
OH, YEAH, FROM THE VERY,
VERY BEGINNING.
NOW THAT HE DOES, HE'S CRANKING
OUT FIRST-RATE BREAKFAST,
LUNCH AND DINNER
FOR JUST ABOUT EVERYONE,
FROM YOUNG PROFESSIONALS...
WE'RE REGULARS.
YOU'RE REGULARS?
TO LAWYERS
IN SUITS AND BOOTS...
I JUST LOVE IT.
TO NEWCOMERS TO OLD-TIMERS.
CHARLIE'S A FIXTURE
AROUND HERE.
HE'S BEEN SITTIN' AT THAT STOOL
FOR THE LAST 15 YEARS.
AND TO KEEP HIM THERE,
JESSIE'S DOING EVERYTHING
HIS OWN PARTICULAR WAY.
THIS IS WHERE WE MIX
OUR EGGS AND OUR OMELET.
IT MAKES 'EM FLUFFY.
YOU BEAT 'EM UP
LIKE THAT--
AND IT CHANGES
THE TASTE, TOO.
IT MAKES IT EXCELLENT--
VERY GOOD.
DID YOU
MAKE THIS UP?
THIS IS FROM
EXPERIENCE
FROM ALL THE DINERS THAT
I'VE WORKED IN SINCE 1971.
WOW, IT ALREADY LOOKS
FLUFFY AND FOAMY.
AND IT'LL STAY THAT WAY EVEN
AS KIND OF A HALF-SCRAMBLE,
LOADED WITH VEGGIES,
CHEESE, HAM, BACON
AND FRESH CHORIZO SAUSAGE.
IT'S NOT AS GREASY,
AND IT'S MORE FLAVORFUL.
JESSIE JUST DOES IT RIGHT.
JESSIE'S GOT A WHOLE BAG
OF EGG TRICKS,
LIKE BASTING 'EM
WITH ICE TO STEAM 'EM
AND NO EGGS ON THE GRILL,
WHERE THEY JUST DON'T
COME OUT AS GOOD.
EVEN I WOULDN'T DO THAT
TO HUMPTY DUMPTY.
WHAT PEOPLE DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS THAT IF YOU LOVE BREAKFAST--
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOVE
TO MAKE BREAKFAST AT HOME--
YOU NEED TO OWN A GOOD
LITTLE SKILLET LIKE THIS
JUST TO DO EGGS AND DO
NOTHING ELSE IN IT, RIGHT?
YOU BETCHA.
OF COURSE,
A LITTLE TECHNIQUE NEVER HURT.
OKAY.
OH, DID I DO
SOMETHING WRONG?
NO, THAT
WAS OUTSTANDING.
I LIKE HOW YOU
JUST DO IT LIKE THIS.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE YOU'RE
SINATRA ON STAGE.
(mumbling)
JESSIE'S GOT THE SAME STYLE
WITH EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
THERE'S A LOT
OF STUFF ON HERE.
FROM PANCAKES WITH WALNUTS
OR BLUEBERRIES
OR MOUSE EARS
TO HOMEMADE SAUSAGE GRAVY
SLATHERED ON BISCUITS...
I MEAN, THAT'S SAUSAGE
IN THERE. NOTHING'S FROZEN.
FROM BURGERS
TO PHILLY CHEESESTEAKS
TO SOMETHING CALLED
CINCINNATI SPAGHETTI.
WHERE DOES CINCINNATI
SPAGHETTI COME FROM?
UH, I BETCHA IT CAME
FROM CINCINNATI,
I THINK.
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S IT.
THE THING THAT
MAKES IT CINCINNATI
IS WE'RE GONNA
PUT CHILI ON IT HERE.
OKAY, SO NO BEANS,
JUST MEAT AND SAUCE.
MEAT AND SAUCE.
AND THEN
WE HIT IT WITH--
A LITTLE BIT
OF SHREDDED CHEESE.
HIT IT WITH SOME SHREDDED
CHEDDAR CHEESE.
AND THEN YOU CAN--
YOU CAN JUST PUT ONIONS--
YOU PUT ONIONS
ON IT?
WE'LL PUT ONIONS RIGHT
HERE ON THE TIPPY TOP.
MY NOSE STARTS
TO SMELL THE CHILI,
SO I THINK I'M GETTIN' INTO,
LIKE, SOME CRUNCHY FRENCH FRIES,
AND THEN I GET INTO THE PASTA--
AND I'M A PASTA JUNKIE.
WOW, THAT IS GOOD.
I COULD REALLY EAT THAT.
WHATEVER JESSIE'S COOKING,
AFTER 40 YEARS
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ,
HE'S FINALLY LIVING HIS DREAM.
IF YOU KEEP IT
IN YOUR HANDS,
ONLY YOU CAN DETERMINE
THE QUALITY
OF FOOD YOU'RE
GONNA PUT OUT.
AND YOU HAVE TO HAVE
A SINCERE DESIRE TO PLEASE.
I MADE IT
JUST FOR YOU.
I'VE BEEN EATING HERE 40 YEARS.
THIS IS THE BEST IT'S EVER BEEN.
IN FACT,
SINCE JESSIE TOOK OVER,
THIS 47-YEAR-OLD
WICHITA CLASSIC
THAT HAD BEEN GOING DOWNHILL
HAS BEEN TOTALLY TURNED AROUND.
YOU HAVE GOT THE LIFE
WORKIN', BROTHER.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT--I GOT
THE LIFE OF RILEY HERE,
BECAUSE
I'VE BEEN BLESSED.
EVERYTHING THAT I NEED, I'VE
GOTTEN. ISN'T THAT SOMETHING?
(Guy) SO YOU STARTED WORKING
HERE FIRST OR DATING HIM FIRST?
UH, I ACTUALLY WORKED
ABOUT TWO WEEKS HERE.
YOU WORKED
ABOUT TWO WEEKS?
YEAH.
DID YOU DO THIS
FOR TWO WEEKS?
NO, I DIDN'T
START COOKING.
HE'S TAUGHT ME EVERYTHING
I KNOW ABOUT COOKING.
SO YOU WERE WORKING
THE COUNTER?
I'VE NEVER COOKED
ON A FLATTOP BEFORE.
SHE SURE PICKED IT UP QUICK.
ORDER UP.
BY THE TIME SHE AND JESSIE
WERE ENGAGED,
SANDI SAMMONS
WAS COOKIN' LIKE A PRO.
I GOTTA DO
AN EGG WHITE DENVER.
THEY WANT TO HAVE
ONE O-E BOK HERB HOST
FOR 4 SS
AND A KITU 93.
OH, REALLY?
ONE OVER EASY, BACON,
HASH BROWNS,
WHITE TOAST
AND COFFEE.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME
MORE COFFEE, NASCAR?
NO, I'VE GOT IT RIGHT.
YOU SURE? YOU HAVE
YOUR OWN POT HERE?
OH, YEAH,
WE GOT OUR OWN POT.
SANDY AND LARRY
ARE BIG NASCAR FANS,
SO WE REFER TO THEM AS NASCAR,
BECAUSE WE HAVE A LOT OF SANDYS
AND SEVERAL LARRYS THAT COME IN.
DO WE HAVE--DO WE
HAVE ANYBODY ELSE?
WELL, LET'S SEE, WE HAVE
HAMBURGER JIM, BLUES JIM,
BICYCLE JIM.
I NEED A BEAT 17 OVER
ON SNAGGLEPUSS' BICYCLE TABLE
WITH A W-W
AND A B-F AND A J-K
OVER THERE ON STACK.
NOW WOULDN'T HE BE SURPRISED
IF A PLATE OF FOOD POPPED UP
IN THAT WINDOW?
YEAH, EXACTLY.
JESSIE'S MAKING
ALL KINDS OF--
HE'S GOT LASAGNA AND ICE
CREAM ON THE GRIDDLE.
AND HE'D PROBABLY MAKE IT
IF YOU ORDERED IT.
THIS IS USUALLY,
LIKE, ALL TOGETHER.
THAT'S THE SCRAMBLE.
BUT I MAKE HIM SEPARATE IT.
BUT YOU MAKE HIM
SEPARATE IT.
I DON'T THINK--
HAVE YOU MET JESSIE?
YEAH.
I DON'T THINK THAT
HE'S WORRIED ABOUT THAT.
WHAT I'VE LEARNED,
BASICALLY, FROM JESSIE
IS YOU CAN GO A LOT OF PLACES
AND GET SOMETHING GOOD TO EAT.
YOU CAN GO A LOT OF PLACES
AND GET SOME GOOD SERVICE,
BUT IT'S FEW PLACES WHERE YOU
GET THE COMBINATION OF 'EM BOTH.
AND IT'S A FAMILY THING--
SANDI'S DAUGHTER STEPHANIE,
JESSIE'S NIECE DEIRDRE
AND A WHOLE CROWD OF REGULARS
WHO THINK THEY'RE FAMILY, TOO.
IT'S LIKE HOME.
YOU KNOW, YOU GO TO YOUR
GRANDMA'S KITCHEN, AND YOU EAT.
THIS IS WHAT IT IS.
ASSUMING GRANDMA'S STILL MAKING
HER OWN CRACKER CRUMBS
FOR THE MEAT LOAF...
IT'S A LABOR OF LOVE.
IT'S A GOOD ONE.
HAND-BATTERING AND FRYING
EACH INDIVIDUAL ORDER
OF A KANSAS FAVORITE...
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK--
IT'S EXCELLENT.
EVEN MAKING THAT OLD STANDBY
LIVER AND ONIONS...
I'M GONNA
BE OVER HERE.
FOR THE SEVEN PEOPLE
THAT LIKE IT.
JUST TELL ME WHAT
YOU'RE DOING, JESSIE.
THIS IS GONNA BE THE BEST
PART RIGHT HERE.
THIS
IS THE BEST PART?
YES, BACON GREASE.
YOU GOTTA HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF BACON GREASE.
NOW THAT
I'M IMPRESSED WITH.
THAT I LIKE.
JESSIE SAYS
HE'S SIMPLY COMMITTED
TO MAKING THE OLD-TIME
DINER CLASSICS,
AND THAT INCLUDES DESSERT--
THIS FRESH-FRUIT COBBLER,
35 KINDS OF MILK SHAKES
AND FRESH PIE.
A MENU LIKE THIS WILL TAKE
A 2-MAN CREW ON THAT LINE.
OH, YEAH,
ABSOLUTELY.
CAN THEY GET
THIS MENU ALL DAY?
OH, YES,
BREAKFAST ALL DAY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MY INFATUATION IS
WHEN SOMETHING'S
MAKING NOISE.
I WANT TO ALWAYS
STICK MY FINGER IN IT.
BUT NOT EVEN JESSIE CAN PULL
OFF THE DOUBLE BACKFLIP.
HOW DID YOU DO THAT?
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
THAT WAS FAB--
I'VE NEVER SEEN--
I'VE NEVER DONE THAT.
THANK YOU.
I'LL BE HERE ALL WEEK.
NO, YOU WON'T.
BUT HE WILL,
MAKING A CLASSIC EVEN BETTER
AFTER 40 YEARS OF WAITING
FOR THE CHANCE.
THIS IS NOW
THE JESSIE SHOW.
NEXT, SOME CLASSIC GREEK
GONE MAD.
IT SEEMS A LITTLE JUNKY,
BUT PEOPLE LIKE THAT.
I'M HERE IN BAKER, CALIFORNIA.
VEGAS IS THAT WAY.
L.A. IS WAY THAT WAY.
I'M IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE DESSERT.
SO WHERE DOES THAT PUT ME?
AT THE MAD GREEK.
FOR 20 YEARS,
THIS PLACE HAS BEEN FAMOUS
FOR SERVING TRAVELERS
SOME OF THE MOST OUT-OF-BOUNDS
HOMEMADE GREEK FOOD
YOU'LL FIND ANYWHERE.
IT'S WONDERFUL. I CRAVE THESE
FROM THIS PLACE.
IT JUST HAPPENS TO BE
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
IT'S A NICE BREAK
BETWEEN L.A. AND VEGAS--
EXCELLENT FOOD.
I STOP HERE ALL THE TIME.
AND MAYBE EVEN MORE
OFF THE HOOK THAN THE FOOD
IS THE GUY
WHO STARTED IT ALL...
THAT'S NOT A TUXEDO JACKET.
THAT'S MY...
MAD GREEK MICHAEL DABOUR.
MAD IS MAINLY
ECCENTRIC.
EVERYTHING COMBINED HERE--
IT'S ECCENTRIC.
YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN?
'CAUSE
I WAS GONNA SAY
MAYBE SOMETIME WHEN
YOU HAVE SPARE TIME,
YOU COULD DECORATE.
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THIS IS THE BEST DECORATION
AT ALL. THEY COME FROM NEW YORK.
THERE'S NOT A SPARE PLACE
TO PUT ANYTHING.
I NEED MORE WALLS.
WHY DID YOU EXPAND? JUST
'CAUSE I NEEDED MORE WALLS.
YEAH, I NEED
MORE WALLS.
IT SEEMS A LITTLE JUNKY,
BUT PEOPLE LIKE THAT.
WHEN IT COMES TO KNOWING
WHAT PEOPLE LIKE,
THE MAD GREEK AIN'T SO MAD.
IT'S DELICIOUS. THEY JUST
KNOW WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
WHAT WERE YOU THINKING?
THIS IS BAKER, CALIFORNIA.
YOU CAME AND PUT
A GREEK RESTAURANT
WHERE TYPICALLY THERE'D
BE A TRUCK STOP,
AND THIS PLACE
IS PACKED.
WHEN I CAME HERE,
I WAS BROKE.
"WHEN I CAME HERE,
I WAS BROKE."
THAT'S OFTEN WHY I GET IN
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS, YEAH.
SO YOU DON'T HAVE
TOO MUCH TO LOSE,
AND YOU START DOING
YOUR OWN THING.
WHICH MEANT HAVING A SHOWMAN
SENSE OF THEATER,
FAITH IN HIS FAMILY'S RECIPES
AND THE GOOD SENSE
TO STICK HIS SON LARRY
WITH MOST OF THE WORK.
HE'S THE ONE THAT WORKS
HIS BUTT AND ALL THAT,
AND I COME HERE.
I PICK UP THE MONEY.
AN ANCIENT ANCESTOR.
WAY BEYOND KEEPING UP
THE DéCOR...
THE BIG WRENCH.
THE BIG WRENCH--
THAT'S THE EQUALIZER.
LARRY'S COMMITTED
TO KEEPING UP THE MENU,
CRANKING OUT THE HOMEMADE FOOD
HIS FATHER INSISTED ON
FROM THE VERY BEGINNING.
WE DON'T MESS
WITH GRANDMA'S RECIPES.
YOU JUST DON'T--
IF IT'S NOT BROKEN,
DON'T FIX IT.
RIGHT.
BELIEVE ME, NOTHING'S BROKEN,
LIKE THE SOUVLAKI--
GREEK SHISH KEBAB
MARINATED FOR TWO DAYS
BEFORE BEING SKEWERED
AND SEARED ON THE GRILL.
THERE'S SPANAKOPITA--
THAT'S SPINACH PIE--
AND BAKLAVA MADE WITH FRESH
GROUND PISTACHIOS
AND THE TOP SELLER--
MAYBE THE MOST MISPRONOUNCED
FOOD ON THE FACE OF THE EARTH.
SOME PEOPLE SAY,
"MAKE UP YOUR MIND.
DO I CALL IT GY-RO
OR A YEAR-O?"
I SAY,
"GIVE ME MY 5 BUCKS.
I'LL LET YOU CALL IT
ANYTHING YOU WANT."
..AND CALL IT
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
FOR THE RECORD, IT'S A YEAR-O.
THE CONE COMES IN
AT 40 POUNDS?
CORRECT.
AND IT'S A GROUND MIXTURE
OF LAMB AND BEEF...
CORRECT.
WITH HERBS
AND SPICES.
CORRECT.
IT'S GREAT IN A PITA SANDWICH
WITH A YOGURT-BASED SAUCE
CALLED TZATZIKI.
BUT AS GOOD AS IT IS,
LARRY SAYS THERE'S AN EVEN
MORE AUTHENTIC VERSION.
IS THIS MORE LIKE WHAT
YOU FIND IN GREECE?
YES,
THIS WOULD BE MORE WHAT
YOU FIND IN GREECE.
AND THIS IS CALLED?
WELL, WE'RE CALLING IT
THE SHAWARMA,
BUT IT CAN ALSO BE CALLED
A DONER.
BUT THIS
IS MORE EXPENSIVE,
BECAUSE YOU HAVE
TO MAKE THAT BY HAND?
RIGHT, RIGHT.
OKAY. AND THAT--
YOU HAVE BEEF AND LAMB?
RIGHT.
SO YOU HAVE TO GET THE BONELESS
LAMB, THE BONELESS BEEF,
CUT IT INTO SLICES, POUND IT
OUT, STACK IT TOGETHER...
MARINATE IT,
MARINATE IT.
DO YOU MARINATE IT FIRST
OR AFTER IT'S ON THE STICK?
NO, FIRST.
FIRST. AND THEN YOU GO
AHEAD AND SLIDE IT ON?
RIGHT.
AND YOU GOTTA KEEP IT
SOMEWHAT UNIFORM?
RIGHT.
YEAH, WE TRIM IT.
SO IT SITS ON THERE
THE RIGHT WAY.
IT'S LABOR-
INTENSIVE.
YEAH, IT IS.
SO THIS YOU JUST RUN IT
RIGHT ALONG THE SIDE?
RIGHT.
CAN I TRY
A LITTLE PIECE HERE?
SURE,
GO RIGHT AHEAD.
I THINK I'M GONNA--
I THINK
I CARVED IN BAD.
MMM.
A LITTLE HOT?
IT'S GOT A LITTLE CRUNCH.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE GLAZING,
ALMOST LIKE IT'S
CARAMELIZED A BIT.
PROBABLY SOME OF THE JUICE
FLOWING DOWN AS IT'S COOKING.
WOW. I'M NOT
KIDDIN' YA, MAN.
I THINK IF MORE
PEOPLE--AH, AH--
REALLY KNEW
HOW GREAT THAT WAS,
THE LINE WOULD BE LONGER
THAN IT ALREADY IS.
OF COURSE, PLENTY OF PEOPLE
KNOW ALREADY.
THE SHAWARMA IS ONLY ONE REASON
THE CROWDS KEEP JAMMIN' IN.
WELL, I FEEL SORRY
FOR THE PEOPLE
THAT DON'T COME
ALL THE TIME, LIKE ME.
I GET TO, YOU KNOW, EXPERIENCE
ALL THE DIFFERENT THINGS.
IF YOU'RE JUST COMING THROUGH
TO VEGAS ONCE IN A WHILE,
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE GONNA
GET SOMETHING GREAT,
BUT YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET ALL
THE GREAT STUFF THEY HAVE.
...LIKE THE DEEP-FRIED CALAMARI
SLICED AND BATTERED
FRESH EVERY DAY.
AND SPEAKING OF FRYING...
FRIED ZUCCHINI STICKS.
...HOMEMADE...
(woman) REALLY EXCELLENT.
...TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH.
I'M PRETENDING IT'S HEALTH FOOD.
WHATEVER THE REASON,
FOR TONS OF FOLKS
THE MAD GREEK IS A MUST-STOP.
TELL 'EM IT'S
IN THE DESERT...
IT IS.
IN THE CALIFORNIA
DESERT.
IT'S THE BEST PLACE
IN THE WORLD.
YEAH, WE HAVE NAKED
LADIES ON OUR STATUES.
BUT REMEMBER, IT ISN'T REALLY
WHAT'S ON THE WALLS
THAT MAKES THIS PLACE
SO SPECIAL.
IT'S WHAT'S IN THE KITCHEN.
AND WAIT TILL YOU
SEE THIS RECIPE
FROM LARRY'S GRANDMOTHER...
AND NOW YOU'RE
GIVING IT AWAY ON TV?
YEAH.
AND MY ATTEMPTS
TO PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
YOU GOTTA PUT THE BUTTER
DOWN THERE FIRST THERE, GUY.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
BUTTER FIRST.
THE MAD GREEK
IN BAKER, CALIFORNIA--
NOT YOUR STANDARD
ROADSIDE FAST FOOD JOINT.
YOU'RE LUCKY
YOU'RE EATING NOW,
BECAUSE I WAS ABOUT
TO RAISE MY PRICES.
I'M LUCKY--
WHAT DID YOU JUST--
MY LANDLORD
RAISED THE RENT.
I'M THE LANDLORD.
SELF-PROFESSED MAD GREEK
MICHAEL DABOUR
STARTED THIS PLACE
20 YEARS AGO.
HIS SON LARRY'S
RUNNING IT TODAY,
STILL MAKING THE STUFF
HIS GRANDMOTHER MADE.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE?
SPANAKOPITA.
I MEAN, IS THIS KIND OF LIKE
THE GREEK EGG ROLL?
IT'S AN APPETIZER.
WELL, THAT'S
WHAT I'M SAYING.
SO OKAY--SO YOU CAN PUT IT
WITH EVERYTHING--
GREEK EGG ROLL--
THAT WORKS.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO USE THAT.
YEAH.
SPANAKOPITA ARE SPINACH PIES,
BUT HERE WE'RE MAKING 'EM
FRESH WITH SPINACH,
ONIONS, PARSLEY
AND FETA CHEESE.
HOW MUCH FETA CHEESE DO YOU
GUYS GO THROUGH IN A MONTH?
ABOUT 300,
400 POUNDS.
AND FOR A SWEETER
TASTE--CURRANTS.
MOST PEOPLE DO NOT
PUT CURRANTS IN.
OUR RECIPE
HAS CURRANTS.
MIX IT UP. IT'S TIME
TO FILL AND FOLD.
YOU GOTTA PUT THE BUTTER DOWN
THERE FIRST THERE, GUY.
SORRY.
BUTTER FIRST.
WELL, THERE GOES
THE FOOD PART.
THAT LOOKS LIKE A LITTLE
TOO MUCH, DOESN'T IT?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M GONNA
TAKE SOME OFF.
YEAH, TAKE SOME OFF.
IT LOOKS LIKE
I'M NOT, UM--
YOU'RE FOLDING WRONG.
GO THIS WAY.
OKAY, SO NOW
I COME OVER HERE...
RIGHT, YEAH.
THEN UP.
THERE YOU GO.
FLAG FOLDING 101.
LOOK AT THAT.
I MEAN, I THINK THOSE
ARE DELI CASE-BOUND.
MOST PLACES USE FROZEN.
LARRY SAYS, "FORGET ABOUT IT."
IS THERE THAT MUCH
OF A QUALITY DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THE TWO?
I THINK SO.
IT'S THE SAME REASON
THEY MAKE THEIR BAKLAVA
A PHYLLO DOUGH LAYER AT A TIME
AND THEIR TRADITIONAL GREEK
ALMOND COOKIES BY HAND
A BATCH AT A TIME
AND THE SOUVLAKI
AND THE SHAWARMA FROM SCRATCH.
THAT'S HANDMADE.
THEY DO IT HERE.
IT IS MAD GREEKS'
FOOD.
THEY REALLY DO WANT EATING HERE
TO BE SOMETHING SPECIAL...
THOSE STRAWBERRY SHAKES--
THEY LOOK SO GOOD.
JUST LIKE THE REST
OF THE ENTIRE
MAD GREEK EXPERIENCE.
THANK YOU
FOR COMING BY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
THANKS AGAIN.
NOW THAT'S GOTTA
MAKE YA HAPPY.
THIS GUY HAS HAD IT
ALL ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
AND HE SAYS YOURS
IS THE BEST.
WELL, I KNOW THAT.
HE KNEW IT ALREADY.
I MEAN, HE DOESN'T
TELL ME NOTHING NEW,
BUT I APPRECIATE
HIM SAYING--
HE DOESN'T TELL ME
ANYTHING I DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS WE GOTTA HIT.
WE'LL SEE YA NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
OPEN UP.