I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP, WE'RE GETTING
SOME LOCAL FLAVOR,
LIKE CHILI FROM
AN 85-YEAR-OLD RECIPE
YOU'LL ONLY FIND
AT THIS JOINT IN SEATTLE...
TASTY.
THIS DEFINES CHILI.
WHERE THEY'RE PUTTING IT
ON EVERYTHING BY THE TON.
FEED A FAMILY. COME ON DOWN
TO MIKE'S CHILI PARLOR.
WE'RE HEADING
TO A FOURTH-GENERATION
OKLAHOMA CAFé...
IS THE CHICKEN-FRIED
CHICKEN READY?
WHERE THE LOCAL FLAVORS
ALL COME OUT
OF THAT OLD FAMILY
COOKBOOK...
IT'S JUST LIKE MY MOM
WOULD HAVE MADE.
AND YOU WON'T BELIEVE ONE
OF THE FAVORITES HERE...
FROM THE UNDERSIDE
OF A CALF ACTUALLY.
MOO, MOO, BUCKAROO.
AND WE'RE HEADING TO
A NORTHERN CALIFORNIA JOINT
FAMOUS FOR COOKING
WHATEVER'S AROUND,
LIKE DUNGENESS
CRAB CIOPPINO...
I NEED A HOSE.
HOME-GROWN ARTICHOKES
AND PIE MADE OUT OF BERRIES
MOST FOLKS
NEVER EVEN HEARD OF.
THE OLOLLIEBERRY PIES
ARE FANTASTIC.
OH.
OH, ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SEATTLE IS KNOWN
FOR ITS KILLER FOOD,
AND THERE'S THIS JOINT WE JUST
GOTTA CHECK OUT IN BALLARD--
AN INDUSTRIAL AREA RIGHT ACROSS
THE BRIDGE FROM DOWNTOWN.
THIS THIRD-GENERATION
FATHER-AND-SON TEAM
RUN A ONE-OF-A-KIND PARLOR
FILLED WITH LOCAL FLAVOR.
YOU STIRRING
THAT CHILI OVER THERE?
STIR THE CHILI.
STIR THE CHILI, BIG PHIL.
COME ON, GET TO WORK.
PHIL SEMANDIRIS
AND HIS SON MIKE TAKE
THEIR CHILI VERY SERIOUSLY.
I LOVE IT IN CHILI BURGER,
CHILI DOG--
I LOVE MY CHILI.
AND SO DO THE LOCALS.
HOW WAS IT?
PERFECT.
MM-HMM, MM-HMM.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE KICK?
OH, YEAH.
TASTY.
THIS DEFINES CHILI.
AND CHILI DEFINES EVERYTHING
AT THIS JOINT.
YOU SEE, MIKE'S CHILI PARLOR
IS TRUE TO ITS NAME.
THIS IS YOUR STANDARD
MIKE'S BOWL.
ON WHATEVER YOU ORDER.
CHILI FRIES.
VERY GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVIN'?
CHILI DOG.
CHILI DOG?
MIKE'S CHILI BURGER.
PERFECT.
WHY IS THE GRILLED CHEESE
54 BUCKS?
YOU GOTTA REALLY, REALLY
WANT THE GRILLED CHEESE.
OKAY, IT'S A JOKE,
BUT TRUST ME--
IT AIN'T THE GRILLED CHEESE
THEY'RE COMING FOR.
I LIKE MIKE'S CHILI--
JUST A PLAIN BOWL OF CHILI
WITH CHEESE AND ONIONS.
THERE'S SOMETHING
JUST MAGIC ABOUT IT.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT IT IS.
PHIL WON'T TELL US.
BECAUSE THE RECIPE HAS BEEN
A CLOSELY GUARDED FAMILY SECRET
FOR 85 YEARS.
IS IT WRITTEN DOWN?
NOT WRITTEN DOWN.
NOT WRITTEN DOWN?
NOT WRITTEN DOWN ANYWHERE.
INSTEAD IT'S BEEN PASSED DOWN
FROM MIKE'S GREAT-GRANDFATHER,
ALSO NAMED MIKE.
YOUR GREAT-GRANDFATHER
CAME HERE FROM GREECE.
RIGHT.
AND LIKE A LOT OF GREEKS,
DECIDES TO START COOKING,
SO HE'S COOKING
IN A RESTAURANT,
COMES UP WITH THIS GREAT
CHILI RECIPE, DECIDES HE WANTS
TO LEAVE AND OPEN
HIS OWN RESTAURANT.
IN 1939,
HE BUILT THIS PLACE
WHEN YOU WERE 21,
YOU AND YOUR DAD
TOOK IT OVER TOGETHER.
RIGHT.
IN '66, PHIL STARTED
RUNNING THE PLACE HIMSELF.
20 YEARS LATER,
MIKE JUMPED IN.
SUCK IT IN, BIG GUY.
TOGETHER, THEY'RE PROUD TO TELL
YOU THEY'VE CHANGED
VIRTUALLY NOTHING...
WHERE ARE MY CRACKERS,
MIKE?
ESPECIALLY
WHAT'S IN THE BOWL.
WE DON'T MAKE IT WITH BEANS.
WE DON'T MAKE IT WITH ANYTHING
ELSE THAT I'VE ALWAYS
KIND OF CALLED FILLER STUFF.
WE SERVE IT OVER BEANS.
I THINK THAT REALLY IS
WHAT MAKES IT SPECIAL.
WE JUST PUT THE MEAT
AND THE SECRET SPICE RECIPE
THAT MY, YOU KNOW,
GREAT-GRANDFATHER
STARTED IN THE '20s.
IT'S ALSO THE ALL-DAY
COOKING PROCESS
THAT STARTS WITH BEEF STOCK,
ONIONS AND GARLIC.
WE DIDN'T SAUTéE 'EM.
WE JUST THREW 'EM ALL--
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW THE MEAT.
OKAY, SO MIX, MIX, MIX.
UNTIL IT BREAKS DOWN.
UNTIL IT ALL BREAKS DOWN.
THIS IS LIKE YOUR OWN
LITTLE ATHLETIC WORKOUT.
YOU WANNA ARM WRESTLE?
MAYBE. SO WE'RE MAKING
WHAT WE'RE CALLING SAUCE?
WE'RE MAKING THE SAUCE.
YOU SEE, OUR CHILI
AND OUR BEANS--
THEY NEVER GET
MIXED TOGETHER
UNLESS YOU WANT 'EM
TOGETHER IN A BOWL.
BECAUSE TRUE CHILI--
BY MOST PEOPLE'S STANDARDS--
IS MEAT ONLY.
THAT'S IT.
THIS IS HOW YOU'VE
ALWAYS DONE IT.
ALWAYS.
AND WITH IT ALL RIGHT OUT
IN THE OPEN,
EVERYONE CAN WATCH THESE GUYS
MAKE IT FROM SCRATCH.
I THINK PEOPLE WOULD
GET SCARED IF THEY WALK IN
AND THEY DON'T SEE
THAT POT COOKIN'.
YEAH, THAT'S TRUE.
SOMETIMES THEY DO.
AFTER SEVERAL HOURS
OF SIMMERING,
THE SAUCE IS FINALLY READY
FOR THE BIG BAG OF SPICES.
THERE'S, LIKE, 85 DIFFERENT
SPICES GOING ON IN HERE.
MM-HMM.
WHAT IS IN THIS?
OH, A WHOLE BUNCH OF STUFF.
THERE'S GOTTA BE
SOME CHILI POWDER.
THAT'S WHAT IT--
OREGANO.
I DON'T THINK YOU HAVE
ANY INTENTION OF TELLING ME.
NO--YOU'RE RIGHT.
BUT AT LEAST I--
NO, ABSOLUTELY.
NO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S MORE THAN I'VE EVER
DONE FOR ANYBODY--
FOR ANYBODY ELSE?
I'M ITALIAN.
GREEKS ARE ALMOST
ITALIANS.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
SO HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THIS GONNA HANG OUT?
WELL, ACTUALLY JUST
A LITTLE WHILE NOW.
BE CAREFUL.
WHY?
IT'S ADDICTING?
IT'S ADDICTING.
BE CAREFUL.
WE WARNED YOU.
THAT'S THE ONLY BAD THING
ABOUT THIS CHILI.
MM, THAT'S TASTY.
ISN'T IT?
YOU GUYS SHOULD CALL THIS,
LIKE, A CHILI PARLOR.
IT'D BE A GOOD NAME.
WHILE LOTS OF FOLKS
GO FOR THE BASIC BOWL...
YOU GET OYSTER CRACKERS.
THAT'S A MUST.
IT'S THE CHILI COMBOS THAT'LL
REALLY SPIN YOUR HEAD AROUND.
FAVORITE WAY TO EAT MIKE'S
CHILI IS IN A CHILI BURGER.
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
HOW MUCH IS IT?
6 BUCKS.
FEED A FAMILY. COME ON DOWN
TO MIKE'S CHILI PARLOR.
GO CHEESE FIRST?
YEAH, CHEESE FIRST.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'RE GOING ONIONS.
THAT'S A LITTLE SOFT
FOR A GUY LIKE YOU.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE TALKIN'.
NOW WE'RE TALKIN'.
YOU WANT ME TO DO THE PEPPERS
FOR YOU THIS TIME?
NO. YOU'VE BEEN RIDICULOUS
ON ALL OF THE OTHER
VOLUME PORTIONS.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
I THINK IT'S PERFECT.
OKAY. CAN SOMEONE
REALLY EAT THAT?
OH, YEAH, DEFINITELY.
DO YOU WANT A DEEP BREATH--
TAKE A DEEP BREATH OR SOMETHING?
MM. PRIMO.
THAT'S A PRIMO CHILI BURGER.
NICE SPICE TO IT.
IT'S VERY FLAVORFUL.
THE CHEESE MELTS REALLY QUICK,
'CAUSE IT'S CUT THIN.
YEP.
THEN YOU GET THE REAL
MEATY TEXTURE
OF THE PATTY.
RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW
IF ANYBODY CAN DO
A GOURMET BREAKDOWN ON SUCH
A THING AS A CHILI BURGER,
BUT I GOTTA TELL YA,
THAT BURGER IS IN IT
TO WIN IT RIGHT THERE.
AND IF THE BURGER'S
NOT ENOUGH OF A MEAL,
CHECK OUT THE CHILI PASTA.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
LOOKS GOOD, HUH?
LOOKS GOOD?
THAT'S--
FOR YOU ITALIANS--
THAT'S THE ITALIAN CHILI?
OH, YEAH.
NO, THIS IS WHERE WE START
GETTING INTO THIS.
I MEAN,
I KNOW A FEW THINGS...
ABOUT PASTA?
MM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT THAT?
DO YOU LIKE THAT?
'CAUSE I LIKE THE LITTLE
JALAPEÑO NUGGETS.
THAT'S THE KICKER ON THIS.
YEAH.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
IT FEELS LIKE HOME.
NOTHING BEATS MIKE'S.
'CAUSE MIKE'S CHILI PARLOR
IS STILL DOING IT THE WAY IT'S
BEEN DONE SINCE THE BEGINNING.
THAT'S THE STUFF.
ISN'T IT NICE TO HAVE
A PLACE LIKE THIS SO CLOSE?
IT BEATS THE HECK
OUT OF ALL THE FAST-FOOD STUFF.
LIFE IS SHORT.
WHAT A BETTER WAY
TO SPEND A LOT OF IT.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T CREATE
A PLACE LIKE THIS.
IT HAS TO HAPPEN
OVER TIME.
THIS IS MY
OLDEST CUSTOMER.
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 37, 38--
THEY SAID THEY--YOU KNOW
WHAT THEY JUST TOLD ME?
THEY SAID, "WE DIDN'T EVEN
KNOW HE SERVED CHILI.
WE JUST COME IN
FOR THE ABUSE."
THAT'S TRUE.
COMING UP,
WE'RE HEADING FOR OKLAHOMA,
WHERE THEY'RE FRYING UP
ALL KINDS OF LOCAL FLAVOR...
THAT'S VERY TASTY FOOD.
WITH A SPECIALTY OF THE HOUSE
THEY REALLY WANT ME TO TRY.
YOU GOTTA BE RIGHT IN MY FACE
FOR THIS, DON'T YOU?
WELCOME TO VINITA, OKLAHOMA,
ABOUT AN HOUR NORTHEAST
OF TULSA
IN CATTLE COUNTRY.
NOW WE'RE HEADING TO A PLACE
CALLED CLANTON'S--
A FAMILY-OWNED JOINT
FOR OVER 80 YEARS,
FAMOUS FOR THEIR
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
AND ANOTHER CATTLE
COUNTRY DELICACY
YOU JUST GOTTA CHECK OUT.
EVER HAD CALF FRIES?
I'VE NOT HAD CALF FRIES ANYWHERE
ELSE IN A RESTAURANT LIKE THESE.
CALF FRIES?
CALF.
SOME PLACES KNOW 'EM
AS ROCKY MOUNTAIN OYSTERS.
OTHERS DON'T
KNOW 'EM AT ALL.
THEY COME FROM
THE UNDERSIDE OF THE CALF.
MM.
THEY SAY WHEN YOU'RE
A FIRST-TIME CUSTOMER,
THEY SEND OUT A FREE ORDER.
THEY'RE A CLASSIC HERE,
ALONG WITH
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK...
AND THEY DO USE
THE GOOD SEASONINGS.
AND CHICKEN AND DRESSING...
IT'S JUST LIKE
MY MOM WOULD HAVE MADE.
COUNTRY FAVORITES
AT A LOCAL FAVORITE,
IN THE SAME FAMILY
FOR FOUR GENERATIONS,
STARTING WITH A GUY
NAMED SWEET TATER.
MY GREAT-GRANDFATHER.
SWEET TATER?
SWEET TATER.
BECAUSE HE WAS
A SWEET POTATO FARMER.
WASN'T MAKING
A LIVING AT IT.
SO HE SAID HE'S GONNA
OPEN UP HIS OWN RESTAURANT.
AND 80 YEARS LATER, DENNIS
PATRICK AND HIS WIFE MELISSA--
SHE'S A CLANTON--
ARE KEEPING IT ROLLING.
IS THE CHICKEN-FRIED
CHICKEN READY?
THEY TOOK OVER
ALMOST TEN YEARS AGO
WHEN MELISSA'S PARENTS
RETIRED.
WE WERE BOTH PRETTY BUSY
IN THE CORPORATE WORLD,
AND OUR KIDS WERE GETTING
INTO HIGH SCHOOL AGE,
JUNIOR HIGH AGE,
AND WE SAID,
"WE'RE COMIN' BACK."
NICE.
GOT IT.
REAL FRIENDLY PEOPLE,
GREAT FOOD.
IT'S JUST A NICE,
HOMEY PLACE.
A HOMEY PLACE
WHERE THEY'RE HOME COOKING
THOSE HOMEMADE CALF FRIES.
(Dennis) THE GOVERNOR
AND HIS WIFE
COME IN HERE--
SHE LOVES 'EM.
YOU HAVE THE BEST
CALF FRIES IN OKLAHOMA?
THAT IS THE FIRST LADY
OF OKLAHOMA TELLING YOU THAT.
AND HERE WE HAVE
OKLAHOMA'S FINEST
CALF FRIES.
WHERE DOES ONE
HARVEST THESE?
FROM THE UNDERSIDE
OF A--
OF A CALF ACTUALLY.
AH!
YEAH, THE BATTER'S
GONNA MATTER.
CHICKEN BASE,
GROUND MUSTARD,
LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER IN HERE.
JUST POUR THAT IN THERE.
THE WHOLE THING?
YES, SIR.
OH, IT'S CHUNKY.
WELL, IT'S BUTTERMILK.
WITH A CORNMEAL CAYENNE
FLOUR DREDGE.
CAYENNE.
KILL IT, KILL IT.
NOW WE JUST DUMP 'EM
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
(Dennis) SEE?
THEY DIDN'T EVEN SCREAM.
YOU GOTTA BE RIGHT IN MY FACE
FOR THIS, DON'T YOU?
NOT BAD.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
GOT ANY HOT SAUCE?
DIGGIN' IT
WITH THE BLUE CHEESE.
CHICKEN-FRIED
CALF FRIES
BUFFALO WING STYLE.
HOT.
THAT WAS GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I LIKE
THE BIG ONES YET.
LOOK AT THAT
RIGHT THERE, HUH?
MOO, MOO, BUCKAROO.
CALF FRIES? YOU NEED
KETCHUP WITH THOSE FRIES?
DO THEY EVER DO, LIKE,
CALF FRIES SEVICHE,
CALF FRIES
ON THE HALF SHELL, OR...
HOW DID YOU LIKE
THE CALF FRIES?
WE WERE ANXIOUS TO SEE
HOW YOU LIKED THOSE.
THEY WERE VERY UNIQUE.
I LIKE SMALLER ONES.
THE COUPLE THAT I HAD
WERE VERY BIG--
LIKE, THE WHOLE FAMILY
WAS THERE.
WE PRIDE OURSELVES ON CARRYING
OVER THE TRADITION
THAT STARTED ACTUALLY
80 YEARS AGO.
AND NOT JUST THE CALF FRIES--
THEY'RE KEEPING EVERYTHING
CLASSIC,
LIKE THEIR
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK--
NOT DEEP FRIED,
BUT COOKED ON THE FLAT TOP.
NOW THIS IS
THE AWARD-WINNING...
WORLD-ACCLAIMED...
WORLD-ACCLAIMED.
AS READ IN
"GOURMET" MAGAZINE.
THAT'S A PRETTY
HIGH HONOR.
YOU GOTTA HAVE TWO HANDS.
ONE'S THE DRY HAND--
THE WET HAND
AND THE DRY HAND, BABY.
AND THE DRY HAND.
I'VE PLAYED THIS.
OKAY, YOU'VE DONE
THIS BEFORE?
OH, YEAH.
WHAT CUT OF MEAT IS THIS?
THIS IS A CUBE STEAK.
GET 'EM IN FRESH...
NEVER FROZEN.
SO THAT'S A BIG THING.
SEE? THAT'S
A BIG DEAL RIGHT THERE.
WE START IN THE MIDDLE,
AND JUST PRESS IT OUT
AROUND THE SIDES.
YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
LOVE YOUR CHICKEN FRY,
AND IT'LL LOVE YOU.
WE DON'T DEEP FRY IT.
WE COOK IT ON THE FLAT GRILL.
THIS IS WHAT THEY
DID 80 YEARS AGO,
AND WHEN WE TOOK IT OVER,
I WAS PRETTY MUCH TOLD
WE WOULD CONTINUE
THE SAME WAY IT HAS BEEN,
OR I'D BE RUN
OUT OF TOWN.
SHOULD YOU BE ABLE TO EVALUATE
A GOOD CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
BY BEING ABLE
TO CUT IT WITH A FORK?
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE
TO CUT IT WITH A FORK
AND JUST HAVE IT KIND OF
ALMOST MELT IN YOUR MOUTH THERE.
BUT I GOTTA TELL YOU,
I COULD PUT DOWN
6 OR 15 OF THESE.
THAT'S PRETTY
MACK DADDY, MAN.
THANK YOU.
THEY USE THEIR SEASONINGS ON
THEIR STEAKS LIKE I DO AT HOME.
TWO ICED TEAS.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
AND FOR THE FOLKS
IN THIS SMALL TOWN,
CLANTON'S HAS BEEN
KIND OF AN EXTENSION
OF THEIR OWN DINING ROOM AS FAR
BACK AS THEY CAN REMEMBER.
APPRECIATE Y'ALL
COMIN' IN.
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY
KIND OF GETS TOGETHER,
AND THEY KNOW ONE ANOTHER,
AND IT'S NICE.
IT'S LIKE SITTIN'
AT MAMA'S TABLE.
IS IT REALLY?
YES.
WITHOUT DOWN-HOME FAVORITES
LIKE FRIED CATFISH,
HOMEMADE APPLE PIE
AND CLANTON'S LEGENDARY
CHICKEN AND DRESSING.
CHICKEN--
BOIL IT TILL IT SHREDS...
RIGHT.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND FOR THE DRESSING,
GRAB SOME HOMEMADE CORN BREAD,
JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
JUST HANDED DOWN.
I'M GONNA ASSUME
IT'S SWEET TATER'S RECIPE.
GET THE EGG
OUT OF THE WAY.
THE EGGS, THE SPICES,
AND I'M KIND OF
THE SAME WAY--
YOU WANT ME TO SET IT
ON HIGH AND HIT IT FAST?
YEAH.
THROW IT IN THE OVEN
ABOUT 45 MINUTES,
AND WE USE A SCOOP.
NOW ADD THE CHICKEN...
SHRED IT?
NO, WE JUST--
THROW IT ON THERE?
WE JUST
THROW IT ON THERE.
AND THEN THIS IS OUR
YELLOW CHICKEN GRAVY.
OH, GET OUTTA HERE.
THAT IS--
THAT--THAT IS--
THAT'S THANKSGIVING
IN A BOWL RIGHT THERE.
EVERY DAY.
EVERY DAY
AND EVERY DISH
FOR EVERY ONE OF 80 YEARS.
LIKE YOU'D GET
AT HOME.
JUST A REAL
SAVORY TASTE.
A FEW MORE MINUTES
HERE, BUD.
I'VE ATE HERE
EVER SINCE
I BEEN 6, 7 YEARS OLD.
THAT'S WHERE I'VE ALWAYS COME.
THANK YA.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
THANK YOU.
YOUR ORDER OF CALF FRIES
ARE COMIN' OUT RIGHT NOW.
OH, SUPER.
HOW MANY YOU HAVE?
YOU GOTTA EVOLVE.
PEOPLE ARE ALWAYS CHANGING,
EXCEPT THEY'LL SAY,
"HEY, THAT'S GREAT.
LET'S TRY THAT ON THE MENU.
LET'S PUT SOMETHIN' FANCY
ON THERE, BUT I'M GONNA EAT
MY CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK."
AND YOU GET EMOTIONAL
ABOUT THIS.
I DO. I LOVE THIS PLACE.
COMING UP,
WE'RE HEADING WEST
TO ANOTHER
FOURTH-GENERATION JOINT...
THAT'S BEEN HERE
SINCE 1890?
YEAH, 1894.
IT'S A FANTASTIC
PLACE TO COME.
WHERE THE LOCAL FLAVORS
ARE TOTALLY CALIFORNIA.
OH, SO GOOD.
CRUISIN' THE COAST
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA,
YOU GOTTA LOVE IT--
THE OCEAN, THE SEAFOOD,
THE FARMS.
WELL,
THERE'S THIS COOL PLACE
IN A LITTLE TOWN
CALLED PESCADERO
WHERE THE DUARTE FAMILY HAS BEEN
SERVING UP RIGHTEOUS FOOD
FOR OVER FOUR GENERATIONS.
UH-HUH.
IT'S GREAT.
THERE'S NOTHING ON THE MENU
THAT I WOULDN'T ORDER AGAIN.
THIS TIME WE'RE GOING
WITH A CRAB MELT.
FRESH CRACKED CRAB--
IT'S A GIVEN.
THAT'S WHAT
WE COME DOWN AND WE HAVE.
BE RIGHT BACK
FOR THE CLAMS.
FROM OYSTERS ON THE HALF SHELL
TO FRESH COHO TROUT...
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD
HERE IS REALLY GOOD.
THERE'S NO MISTAKIN'
WHAT DUARTE'S TAVERN
IS ALL ABOUT.
IT'S GREAT.
ONE OF THE IDEALS OF
THE RESTAURANT WAY BACK WHEN
WAS TO FEATURE
LOCAL PRODUCTS.
IT'S BEEN HERE
SINCE 1890?
YEAH, 1894.
1894.
THAT WAS JUST THE BAR.
THEN MOST OF ALL THIS--
YEAH, BUT GRANTED--
THEN MOST OF ALL THIS
WAS 1935.
YEAH. 1935--THAT'S
QUITE A BIT OF NOSTALGIA.
YEAH, YEAH.
FOR TIM DUARTE, EVERYTHING'S
GOTTA BE AT LEAST AS GOOD
AS IT'S ALWAYS BEEN...
YEAH, THAT'S MY DAD
FISHERMAN RON.
SO HE'S STAYING TRUE
TO THE OLD RECIPES,
LIKE CRAP CIOPPINO,
KIND OF A SEAFOOD STEW
FILLED WITH FRESH
DUNGENESS CRAB.
(Guy) IN MY OPINION...
(Tim) YEAH.
NOTHING BETTER
THAN THE DUNGENESS.
YOU KNOW, AND THEN WE'RE
SO CLOSE TO HALF MOON BAY,
WE CAN GET--YOU KNOW, WE HAVE--
RIGHT OFF THE BOAT BASICALLY.
WE SPEND A LOT OF TIME
CRACKING CRAB.
SO THERE'S A PINCHER.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S CRACKED,
CRACKED, CRACKED AT EVERY JOINT,
BUT STILL INTACT,
BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT A WHOLE
BUNCH OF LITTLE, TINY PIECES.
YOU WANT LEGS IN THERE,
SO WE'LL PUT IT IN HERE.
SO WE GOT SOME CLAMS.
THREE LITTLE NECK CLAMS.
PER ORDER?
PER ORDER.
WE PUT THREE JUMBO
WHITE PRAWNS PER ORDER.
WE PUT A PIECE OF
PACIFIC ROCK COD...
OKAY.
PER ORDER,
AND THEN THE CRAB.
NEXT UP, A LIGHT TOMATO SAUCE
WITH AN UNEXPECTED SPICE.
THE KEY INGREDIENT TO OUR
CIOPPINO SAUCE IS CUMIN.
THAT'S KIND OF
OUR SIGNATURE THING.
YOU WANT AN INCH
OF SAUCE IN THERE.
RIGHT ON TOP?
RIGHT ON TOP.
THAT'S GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SAY 1/4 CUP,
MAYBE 1/3 OF A CUP
OF CLAM JUICE.
WE HAVE SOME WHITE WINE, WHICH
WE'RE GONNA TWIRL IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT, AND THEN WE JUST
PUT THE LID ON IT.
SO IT'S GONNA BE
A CROSS BETWEEN
SIMMERING IT IN THERE
AND STEAMING IT?
YES.
WHEN DO WE KNOW
IT'S READY?
WHEN THE CLAMS ARE OPEN
AND IT'S SIMMERING,
IT'S DONE.
OKAY.
RIGHT THERE. PERFECT.
SO KIND OF GIVE IT THIS
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
OH, OH, OH.
THE PIèCE de RéSISTANCE--
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF GREEN
ON TOP FOR COLOR,
THEN THERE IT IS.
BON APPéTIT,
AS THEY SAY, HUH?
I'M GONNA GET DOWN
ON IT.
LET ME GIVE YOU
A BIB, TOO.
NO BIB.
NO BIB?
YOU'RE GOING UNPROTECTED?
NO, I AM GONNA BE
IN IT TO WIN IT.
YEAH.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THIS--
THE MACHINE.
I BET.
OH, I CAN TELL.
WE'LL DO THAT.
I CAN TELL.
CUCKOO!
THAT WAS A GOOD BITE,
WASN'T IT?
OH, DUDE, DID YOU HEAR
THE SLURPER ON THAT ONE?
OH, THIS IS SO GOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
LET ME SAY THIS,
AND I DON'T SAY THIS OFTEN
'CAUSE I DON'T LIKE
TO QUALIFY
THAT ANYTHING
SPECIFICALLY IS THE BEST--
THAT MIGHT BE SOME OF
THE BEST CIOPPINO
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
I NEED A NAP
AND A HOSE.
AND I DIDN'T GET
ANY ON ME.
FOLKS DRIVE HOURS FOR THIS...
SO WHICH PART IS YOUR FAVORITE
PART OF THE CIOPPINO?
THE CRAB.
AND EVERYTHING ELSE
ON THE MENU--
NOT JUST BECAUSE
THE FOOD'S OFF THE HOOK,
BUT BECAUSE IT'S THE WAY
THEY REMEMBER IT.
IT'S A FAMILY TRADITION
THAT'S BEEN PASSED ON
FOR GENERATIONS
AND GENERATIONS.
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE FEW
PLACES YOU CAN STILL GET
A RARE CALIFORNIA SPECIALTY
DONE RIGHT--A BIG, RICH,
WEST COAST SHELLFISH CALLED
ABALONE ON HOMEMADE SOURDOUGH.
SO LET'S MAKE ONE.
OKAY.
WE GIVE IT AN EGG WASH,
GIVE IT A VERY LIGHT--
LIGHT DUST?
LIGHT DUSTING
OF CRACKER MEAL.
OKAY.
WE'LL DO THAT TO OUR--WE GET
TWO LITTLE CUTLETS PER SANDWICH.
WE'LL BRING IT
OVER HERE.
SO IT DOESN'T GET FRIED,
IT GOES FLAT TOP?
IT GOES FLAT TOP GRILL.
SEE HOW IT'S STARTING TO GET
GOLDEN BROWN RIGHT THERE?
THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR.
WE'RE DONE, SO WE GOT
THE SLICED SOURDOUGH.
PUT IT ON THERE
JUST LIKE THAT.
NO LETTUCE,
NO TOMATO, NO NADA--
DON'T INTERRUPT PERFECTION.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, THAT IS SO KILLER.
YEAH, IT'S A GOOD,
HOT ITEM.
MM.
IF ANYBODY KNOWS ABALONE,
THIS IS--
THIS IS THE BOMB.
THAT IS SUCH A RICH--
I MEAN,
THE FLAVOR'S SO DEEP,
AND THE SEAWEED ADDS
SOME TEXTURE--OH.
TEXTURE OF THE BREAD--
JUST DON'T TALK
DURING THIS.
SEAFOOD IS THE BEST.
BUT IT ISN'T JUST
THE SEAFOOD.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
HERE IN ARTICHOKE COUNTRY,
DUARTE'S IS GROWIN' THEIR OWN--
WAIT TILL YOU SEE WHAT FOR.
MM. WOW, THAT IS GOOD.
AT DUARTE'S TAVERN
IS PESCADERO, CALIFORNIA,
THEY'RE TOTALLY
INTO LOCAL FLAVOR.
IT'S A FANTASTIC
PLACE TO COME.
FRESH FROM THE PACIFIC,
AND FROM THEIR OWN LITTLE PIECE
OF LAND JUST DOWN THE STREET.
OH, YEAH.
WE'LL USE THAT, AND MAKE
ARTICHOKE SOUP OUT OF IT.
THE ARTICHOKE SOUP--
(exhales deeply)
I CAN'T TELL YOU
THE AMOUNT OF PEOPLE THAT WILL
JUST WALK IN THE DOOR AND SAY,
"IS THIS THE PLACE
WITH THE ARTICHOKE SOUP?"
IT'S OFF THE HOOK,
BUDDY!
IF WE GET HIM SOME SPIKED BLONDE
HAIR, HE COULD DOUBLE IN FOR ME.
ALL RIGHT, SO TALK
TO ME ABOUT THE SOUP.
HOW DO WE START THIS?
WE START WITH WHOLE BUTTER,
CHICKEN BROTH.
CHICKEN BOUILLON TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE MORE INTENSE FLAVOR.
OKAY, SO THESE
ARE THE ARTICHOKES.
THESE ARE COOKED
WITH SALT, PEPPER,
A LITTLE OIL AND GARLIC.
THEY SHOULD BE SOMEWHAT FIRM...
OH, DELICIOUS!
'CAUSE WE DON'T WANT
TO OVERCOOK 'EM.
THREE HANDFULS.
WE'RE ANTICIPATING
SPLASHING?
YEAH, IT MIGHT SPLASH.
COOL. I'LL BE OVER HERE.
THIS IS OUR OLD BLENDER.
COME HERE, GUY.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
THIS IS HIGH TECH.
OKAY, THAT'S WHAT WE DO.
SOUNDS LIKE IT'S
ABOUT READY TO LAUNCH.
NOW WE ADD IT TO THE POT.
NOW IS IT SUPPOSED TO HAVE
A LITTLE CHUNK?
YOU DON'T WANNA COMPLETELY
PURéE IT AND LIQUEFY IT.
'CAUSE YOU WANT IT
TO HAVE SOME TEXTURE.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
THE TEXTURE IN THERE.
I'M GONNA PUT SALT,
PEPPER AND GARLIC IN IT...
OKAY.
AND THEN SIMMER IT,
AND AT THE VERY END,
WE'LL PUT THE CREAM IN--
WHOLE WHIPPING CREAM.
THAT'S THE END
OF THE ARTICHOKE SOUP.
THAT'S HOW YOUR DAD
WAS DOING IT BACK--
IT'S BEEN THE SAME RECIPE--
BACK IN THE 1960s.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IS THAT A SHOVEL?
YEAH, WELL, ONLY FOR PEOPLE
WITH BIG MOUTHS.
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THAT'S NICE AND VELVETY.
OH, IT'S REALLY GOOD, MAN.
GREAT.
SIGNATURE ITEM.
I NOW LIVE ON THE EAST COAST,
SO I HAVE TO GET BACK HERE
FOR MY ARTICHOKE SOUP
AS OFTEN AS POSSIBLE.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WHAT DO WE EAT NOW?
THE DESSERTS
ARE GREAT.
THE OLOLLIEBERRY PIES
ARE FANTASTIC.
THE WHAT BERRY?
OLOLLIEBERRY PIE
à LA MODE.
OLOLLIEBERRIES ARE FOUND
MOSTLY IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
THEY TASTE KIND OF LIKE
BLACKBERRIES, BUT SWEETER,
AND THEY MAKE A RIGHTEOUS
HOMEMADE PIE.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES
THIS PLACE SPECIAL.
OH.
OH, ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
HAVE YOU DIED
AND GONE TO HEAVEN YET?
OH, IF I DID, I'D BE THERE
IN A BOWL OF CIOPPINO.
OH, THIS IS SO GOOD.
BUT THERE'S ALSO
THE ABALONE SANDWICH
AND THE ARTICHOKE SOUP.
OH, AND I'LL TAKE
SOME OF THE SOUP
AND THE PIE HOME AS WELL.
AND ALL OF THE OTHER LOCAL
FLAVORS THAT KEEP FOLKS
PASSIONATE ABOUT THIS PLACE
DECADE AFTER DECADE.
(speaking indistinctly)
SO WHEN--
HEY!
YOU CAN'T HAVE YOUR ARM
IN A SLING WHEN YOU'RE WORKIN'.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
AND THEN NOW PUT
THE CELL PHONES IN, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHEN WE ADD
THOSE TASTY MORSELS.
I DON'T KNOW--
I DON'T KNOW WHO'S THOSE ARE.
IT SAYS, "PAROLE OFFICER,"
SO I DON'T KNOW...