HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LATE AT NIGHT,
I LIKE BREAKFAST.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THE FIRST THING I THINK OF IS
WHAT AM I GOING TO GET
AT THE DINER?
WE'RE GOIN' AROUND THE CLOCK
AT JOINTS OPEN 24/7.
(man) IF YOU'RE FEELIN'
LIKE AN OMELET
AT YOU KNOW,
3:00 IN THE MORNING.
IN SAN DIEGO...
I'VE NEVER BEEN TO A PLACE
LIKE THIS BEFORE.
THE EAST COAST DINER
FOR A WEST COAST CROWD...
I GET OFF WORK LATE.
WHOLE BELLY IPSWICH?
CLAMS? YOU HAVE
THEM FLOWN HERE?
STIR-FRY.
THAT IS THE FUNKIEST
CHEESESTEAK I'VE EVER HAD.
THE 24/7 CHICAGO LEGEND...
(Guy) HOLY MOLY!
WHERE THEY'VE
ALWAYS BEEN EATIN' BIG...
WHATEVER'S ON THE MENU DURING
THE DAY IS AT NIGHT, TOO.
LOOK AT THE CROWD.
YOU KNOW THEY'VE BEEN
COMIN' HERE FOR YEARS.
AND AROUND THE CLOCK
IN PHILLY...
WE HAD A LONG NIGHT
LAST NIGHT.
DID YOU?
WE DID.
WITH THE REAL-DEAL
PHILADELPHIA MENU.
CHICKEN CROQUETTE.
REMINDS ME EXACTLY OF WHAT I
USED TO HAVE WHEN I WAS LITTLE.
CHICKPEAS.
IT'S GOOD.
(man) IT'S GOTTEN A BAD RAP.
NOT WHEN IT'S MADE HERE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN I'M THINKING 24/7,
I'M THINKING DINERS,
YOU KNOW, WHATEVER YOU WANT
WHENEVER YOU WANT IT,
LIKE THE STUDIO DINER HERE
IN SAN DIEGO.
THEY'RE HANDLIN'
THE DINNER CROWD,
GETTIN' READY FOR
THE OVERNIGHT CROWD,
AND FOR THOSE WHO WANT
BREAKFAST?
WELL, ANY TIME AT ALL.
TWO HASH BROWNS!
IT'S LIKE
AN OLD-FASHIONED DINER.
IT'S OPEN 24 HOURS A DAY.
(man) FISH AND CHIPS
IN THE WINDOW.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
LATE AT NIGHT,
I LIKE BREAKFAST.
IT'S GOT REALLY GREAT FOOD.
THIS IS AN ORIGINAL.
AND SO IS OWNER
STU SEGALL.
THIS FORMER BOSTONIAN MISSED
THE DINERS HE GREW UP WITH
BACK EAST...
JUMBIE ROLL COMIN'!
SO HE BUILT ONE
HERE IN SAN DIEGO.
IT WAS A FUN PROJECT.
SALAD UP TOP.
ALWAYS HAD FOND MEMORIES
OF GOIN' WITH MY FAMILY
TO THE DINER AND I WAS LOOKIN'
TO BUY A SMALL, TINY,
20-STOOL KINDA THING, YOU KNOW?
TURNED INTO A MONSTER.
I MEAN, EVERYTHING
IS TOP-NOTCH.
THAT'S THE STU THAT DOESN'T KNOW
WHEN TO STOP SIDE OF THINGS.
THERE'S ALSO
THE STU DIDN'T KNOW
HOW TO COOK SIDE OF THINGS,
SO HE WENT AND FOUND
A DINER VETERAN...
LET ME HAVE SOME
PEPPER JACK, PLEASE.
JOHN SAN NICOLAS.
ON ALL THESE RECIPES
THAT GO ON HERE,
YOU KNOW HOW
TO MAKE EVERYTHING?
EVERYTHING.
COLESLAW, ONE TIME.
JOHN WAS BORN IN GUAM,
LEARNED THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
IN THE U.S.,
AND NOW HE'S EAST COAST
COOKIN'...
JUMBIE ROLL COMIN'!
FOR A WEST COAST CROWD.
EXCELLENT.
ROLLIN' OUT
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK,
A PASTRAMI REUBEN...
VERY MESSY.
VERY GOOD.
HUGE FISH AND CHIPS...
I WASN'T EXPECTIN'
THAT BIG A PIECE.
AND A TURKEY, HAM AND CHEESE
SANDWICH CALLED A MONTE CRISTO
THAT'S BATTERED,
DEEP-FRIED AND DUSTED
WITH POWDERED SUGAR.
IT'S LIKE A SANDWICH FELL
INTO MY FRENCH TOAST.
THE MELT DID OPEN UP
ALL THE FLAVOR
OF THE HAM AND TURKEY
CRUNCHY EXTERIOR.
HOLY BANANAS.
THIS IS A GREAT PLACE.
(woman) THEY HAVE
A NICE ATMOSPHERE,
AND, UH, THE FOOD
IS VERY, VERY GOOD.
WE LIVED IN MAINE FOR A TIME
WHILE MY HUSBAND WAS IN COLLEGE.
THIS FOOD IS JUST LIKE
WHAT WE HAD THERE--
MAINE LOBSTER.
YEAH, YOU HEARD HER--
MAINE LOBSTER
FOR REAL-DEAL LOBSTER ROLLS.
A LITTLE CELERY.
JUST A LITTLE MAYONNAISE.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
AND THAT'S JUST THE START
OF STU'S NEW ENGLAND THING.
CLAM ROLLS.
WHOLE BELLY... IPSWICH?
IPSWICH.
THAT'S IN MASSACHUSETTS
WHERE THESE CLAMS COME FROM
AND WHERE STU GREW UP.
YOU HAVE THEM FLOWN HERE
THREE TIMES A WEEK?
ABSOLUTELY, YEP.
WHY NOT JUST GO GET SOME CLAMS
FROM THE LOCAL SEAFOOD?
'CAUSE, UH--
THERE'S REALLY
SOMETHING?
THERE'S REALLY SOMETHING.
WELL, UNLEASH THE CLAM.
GET 'EM DRAINED.
DO WE RINSE 'EM?
YEAH, THESE GUYS
GET RINSED OFF.
BUTTERMILK--
SOAKED IN BUTTERMILK.
NOW HOW LONG
DO THEY SOAK?
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR--
TILL WE GET BACK TO 'EM.
CLAMS OUTTA THE BUTTERMILK.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A CORN FLOURING TO IT.
LIGHTLY DREDGED,
NOT HEAVY PACKED.
LOOSEN 'EM UP A LITTLE BIT,
AND LET HER GO.
HOT AND FAST.
LITTLE TARTAR SAUCE.
FULL BELLY AND ALL.
YES.
MMM.
VERY MILD FLAVOR.
I DO THINK I DO SEE YOU'D WANT
IT TO BE THE BELLY FULL.
IF YOU DIDN'T, THEN IT WOULD
JUST BE ALL, LIKE, FRIED...
NOTHING, BUT IT IS SWEET.
GOOD CLAM.
THE BEST.
THE BREADING WASN'T
TOO, UH, HEAVY
OR TOO CRISP.
IT WAS JUST REALLY GOOD.
WHETHER THEY'RE ORDERING
NEW ENGLAND SEAFOOD...
HOW IS THAT CHOWDER?
IT'S--IT'S DELICIOUS.
OR EGGS AFTER DARK...
OUT HERE FEASTIN'
ON SOME BREAKFAST.
ESPECIALLY AFTER HOURS,
ALL KINDS OF FOLKS
HAVE ADOPTED THIS JOINT
AS A PLACE TO HANG OUT.
MMM.
AMANDA SELLS VINTAGE CLOTHING.
IT'S OPEN LATE.
I GET OFF WORK LATE.
JASON'S A MUSICIAN.
MIDNIGHT, 1:00,
MAYBE LATER.
AND JARED PATROLS
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I SPREAD MY STUFF OUT,
WRITE MY REPORTS,
AND FINISH UP
MY WORK FOR THE DAY,
'CAUSE I FINISH AT MIDNIGHT.
BUT AT ANY HOUR, IT'S
THE FOOD THEY'RE COMIN' FOR.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S PERFECT.
SAMSON'S STEAK SANDWICH.
THAT'S THE ONE.
MY DAD'S NAME IS SAM...
AND YOU'RE HIS SON.
AND I'M HIS SON,
SO IT'S SAM-SON'S SANDWICH.
AND HIS NAMESAKE SANDWICH
IS A PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
WITH A COUPLE OF TWISTS.
SO HOW DO WE MAKE IT?
IT'S MADE WITH PRIME RIB.
SO YOU'RE GONNA TRIM
ALL THE FAT OFF THIS?
ALL THE FAT OFF THIS.
GONNA SLICE IT
THIN AS I CAN.
THAT WOULD MAKE SOME MONEY
CARPACCIO.
AND GET THIS TWIST.
LITTLE PINEAPPLE JUICE?
YOU GOT ABOUT A CUP
AND A HALF OF SOY SAUCE.
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
MEETS TERIYAKI.
GARLIC.
AND WE HAVE SUGAR.
AND A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
AND PEPPER.
SESAME SEED OIL.
THAT SMELLS GREAT.
TAKE THE MEAT,
PLACE IT IN THERE.
I'M GONNA GET MY VEGGIES GOIN'--
SPINACH,
SOME ONION, LITTLE MUSHROOMS,
AND ONE MORE THING--
THE BEAN SPROUTS.
OKAY, THAT'S WHERE
YOU LOSE ME.
I MEAN, I'M DOWN
WITH THE SPINACH,
AND I GOT IT GOIN' ON WITH
THE MUSHROOMS AND THE ONION.
THAT WORKED,
BUT BEAN SPROUTS?
I LEARNED THIS AT BRINT'S DINER
IN WICHITA, KANSAS.
IT'S THE GENTLE
FRANK SINATRA KICK.
AND SO WE GET THIS GOIN'.
THAT GOES A LITTLE
MEDIUM RARE.
YES.
JUST HIT THOSE
RIGHT ON TOP?
RIGHT ON TOP.
WE FINISH IT WITH SOME,
UH, MOZZARELLA.
PUT IT UPSTAIRS.
LET IT MELT.
AND AWAY WE GO.
AH, A MAN THAT'S WORKED
IN THE KITCHEN A FEW YEARS.
THAT DIDN'T SCARE YOU.
THAT IS JUST CRAZY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS ONE
JUICY SANDWICH.
THAT MEAT IS TENDER.
THAT'S GOOD, MAN.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
STIR-FRY
MEETS PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
GOOD COMBINATION.
IT IS.
IT'S A GREAT COMBINATION.
THAT IS THE FUNKIEST
CHEESESTEAK I'VE EVER HAD.
I'D ORDER THAT
15 MORE TIMES.
AND AT ANY HOUR OF THE DAY.
LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE
ON THE MENU HERE,
THEY'RE HOME COOKIN' IT
WHENEVER YOU SHOW UP.
THIS IS GOOD.
'CAUSE WE WERE TOO LAZY
TO EAT EARLIER,
SO NOW WE'RE HERE AT NIGHT.
YEAH, I'VE NEVER BEEN
TO A PLACE LIKE THIS BEFORE.
I'M FROM GEORGIA.
PEAR SALAD?
YOU GONNA BE ABLE
TO FINISH THAT, YOU THINK?
OH, YEAH, AND WE
GOT THAT, TOO.
AND YOU GOT THIS, TOO.
OH, YES, OF COURSE.
AND I SEE THE MENU.
IT KIND OF MORE SEEMS
LIKE IT'S THINGS YOU LIKE
OR THAT YOUR BUDDIES LIKE.
OR THAT YOU JUST
KINDA MADE--
IT--IT SHOULD
JUST SAY "STU'S."
WELL, IT DOES.
IT DOES.
YES.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CHICAGO.
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE
STUFF LIKE THIS.
FOR A LITTLE SOMETHIN' LIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
I KNOW ITALIAN RESTAURANTS THAT
DON'T EVEN MAKE IT THAT GOOD.
SO WHEN YOU'RE LOOKIN' TO CHOW
DOWN IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
YOU COULD GO TO A PLACE
JUST 'CAUSE IT'S OPEN,
OR IF YOU'RE LUCKY,
YOU COULD FIND A PLACE
SERVING REAL-DEAL FOOD THAT
YOU'D GO OUT OF YOUR WAY FOR
ANY TIME OF DAY,
LIKE THIS JOINT--
WHITE PALACE GRILL,
OPEN 24/7 SINCE 1939.
VEAL PARMESAN.
I KNOW ITALIAN RESTAURANTS
THAT DON'T EVEN
MAKE IT THAT GOOD.
CATFISH.
FANTASTIC.
THERE YOU GO.
NACHOS!
HOLY MOLY!
COMIN' IN HERE
SINCE JULY OF 1969.
YEAH.
CAN I HAVE A CUP
OF CHILI, PLEASE?
WHERE YOU ROLLIN'
IN FROM?
IT'S A CHARITY EVENT.
WAS IT FUN?
IT WAS EXCELLENT, BUT, UH,
THIS WAS BETTER THAN
THE FOOD THEY HAD THERE BY FAR.
'CAUSE THERE'S NOTHING BETTER
THAN A BIG PLATE
OF DOWN-HOME,
SCRATCH-MADE FOOD
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
YEAH!
WELL, WE'RE OPEN 24 HOURS
A DAY, 365 DAYS A YEAR.
WE NEVER CLOSE.
SO WHY IS THERE A LOCK
ON THE FRONT DOOR?
I DON'T HAVE A KEY.
THERE'S A LOCK.
BUT FOR CODE,
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A LOCK.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A--
IT'S CITY CODE.
YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE THE KEY?
I DON'T HAVE A KEY.
NO KEY.
GEORGE LIAKOPOULOS SAYS
HE JUST NEVER GOT ONE
WHEN HE BOUGHT THE PLACE
FROM THE ORIGINAL OWNER
SIX YEARS AGO.
CAN FOLKS GET THE ENTIRE MENU
THE ENTIRE TIME?
YEAH, 24-HOUR MENU.
WHATEVER'S ON THE MENU DURIN'
THE DAY IS AT NIGHT, TOO.
FROM STEAKS AND SANDWICHES
AT 3:00 A.M...
SUE, WHERE YOUR
CLUBHOUSE GO?
TO BREAKFAST FOR DINNER...
IT LOOKS LIKE
KILLER FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S AWESOME.
REAL HOME COOKIN'
AT ANY HOUR OF THE DAY.
EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
MY GRANDMOTHER, MY GREAT AUNT
USE TO MAKE STUFF LIKE THIS.
SO THE SHORT RIBS
ARE BLUE PLATE SPECIAL?
YEAH, SPECIALS.
WEDNESDAYS AND SATURDAYS.
THESE ARE CHOICE?
YEAH, CHOICE.
'KAY, THEN WE PUT,
UH, GARLIC POWDER.
SEASONING SALT, WHITE PEPPER,
ONION SALT.
WE ALSO GONNA PUT SOME
BAY LEAVES ON TOP.
NOW A LITTLE BEEF STOCK?
YES.
OKAY, SO WE COVER IT.
YES, AND WE COVER IT.
AND IT GOES IN AT 350
FOR 2 1/2 HOURS.
RIGHT.
WHOA, THAT LOOKS TENDER.
THOSE THINGS ARE JUST
TOTALLY FALLIN' APART.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE A BIG FAVORITE
AROUND HERE IN THE WINTERTIME.
OH, MAN, IT'S OUR BEST SPECIAL,
HUH, TONY?
YEAH.
THIS IS GREAT FLAVOR.
ALL JUICY.
GOOD EATS.
AND WHY NOT?
THIS AIN'T GEORGE'S
FIRST RODEO.
(George) MY FATHER
WAS IN THE BUSINESS.
(Guy) NOW YOUR FATHER'S
AN IMMIGRANT FROM GREECE?
YES, HE IS, YES.
WHEN I WAS 13 YEARS OLD,
I STARTED WORKING WITH HIM.
I WENT TO COLLEGE.
I GOT MY COLLEGE EDUCATION.
WHEN HE FOLLOWED HIS FATHER
INTO THE RESTAURANT BIZ...
...OVER 40 YEARS OLD.
HE TOOK DAD'S RECIPES
WITH HIM.
VEGETABLE SOUP.
BEEF STROGANOFF.
AND WHEN HE BOUGHT
THIS PLACE...
WHO MADE UP
ALL THESE RECIPES?
I DID, ACTUALLY.
I-I SAT DOWN WITH MY FATHER,
AND 99% OF THE STUFF
IS HOMEMADE.
YOU DON'T BUY
THE HASH BROWNS?
NO. NO, WE MAKE
'EM OURSELVES.
OUR OWN BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN GRAVY.
THAT'S NOT GRAVY MIX?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
YOU MAKE YOUR
OWN MARINARA?
YEP.
I GOTTA TELL YA,
THAT'S A LITTLE STRANGE,
BECAUSE IN THE WORLD OF 24/7,
A LOT OF THAT STUFF IS LIKE,
I MEAN, COME ON, WE'RE SO BUSY.
WE GOT SO MUCH GOIN' ON.
WE DON'T HAVE TIME TO MAKE IT,
BUT YOU MAKE IT ALL.
WE MAKE IT ALL.
THEY'RE FRESH-ROASTING
THE TURKEY,
COOKING THEIR OWN ROAST BEEF
FOR THE BARBECUE SANDWICHES,
AND FOR THE VEAL PARMESAN,
EVEN THE BREADING
IS MADE FROM SCRATCH.
SO THIS IS
KIND OF LIKE, UH--
LIKE SEASONED BREADCRUMBS,
BUT YOU MAKE YOUR OWN?
RIGHT.
I LIKE IT.
LOOK AT THAT VEAL.
THEN WE PUT 'EM
IN THE FLOUR.
THEN WE DIP IT IN THE EGG.
AND THEN ON
THE BREADCRUMBS. OH.
SO NOW WE COVER IT,
'CAUSE IT HELPS IT COOK
A LITTLE BIT FASTER?
LOOK AT THOSE.
LOOKS GOOD. GONNA POUR A LITTLE
BIT OF SPAGHETTI SAUCE ON TOP,
AND THEN THE CHEESE
AND THEN COVER IT
ONE MORE TIME?
YES.
TO MELT THE CHEESE.
YEAH.
OH, I JONES
FOR VEAL PARMESAN.
THIS--
LOOK AT THAT!
♪♪
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S A BIG PORTION.
A TON OF CHEESE.
THE VEAL'S TENDER, TOO.
DUDE, THAT'S REAL-DEAL.
AND GEORGE JUST HAD TO THROW
A LITTLE GREEK INTO THE MENU
WITH HIS DAD'S CLASSIC
GREEK CHICKEN.
(George) MY FATHER'S BEEN USIN'
THIS RECIPE 50 YEARS.
IT'S REALLY TENDER.
THE JUICES ARE ALL COMING OUT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
OKAY, SO LET'S GO.
CHICKEN...
OKAY, CHICKEN--
GREEK CHICKEN.
SO THESE ARE WHAT--
3-POUND CHICKENS?
YES, HALF A CHICKEN.
PUT THE LEMON JUICE
ON THE CHICKEN
THEN WE PUT THE SPICES--
ONION SALT...
GARLIC POWDER.
UH, WHITE PEPPER
AND OREGANO.
THEN WE PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF, UH, OIL ON TOP.
OKAY.
SO IT BROWNS A LITTLE BIT?
THEN WE BAKE IT
FOR, UH, 1 1/2 HOURS
AT 350.
LOOK AT THAT!
HOLY MOLY!
OH, IT'S SO NICE
AND CRUNCHY AND CRUSTY,
AND THEN UN--
OH.
OKAY, LET'S DO ONE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
CAN YOU SEE THAT?
JUST PULLS APART
WITH THE FORK.
JUICY. TENDER.
GREAT FLAVOR.
THAT'S--IT'S JUST--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOLKS IN CHICAGO
HAVE GOTTA KNOW...
THIS IS--
THIS IS A LANDMARK, MAN.
AND IT HAS BEEN
FOR ALMOST 70 YEARS,
NOT JUST FOR THE FOLKS
WHO LIVE NEARBY.
EASY ACCESS
FROM THE MAJOR INTERSTATES.
I LIVE ON THE SOUTHEAST
SIDE OF THE CITY.
ESPECIALLY
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
THIS JOINT
IS DESTINATION DINING.
WHERE WERE ALL OF YOU?
I SEE A SMILEY FACE.
I SEE AN "X."
(man) AT THE CLUB.
AT THE CLUB.
I COME IN HERE
EVERY NIGHT.
EVERY DAY,
ME AND HIM ARE HERE,
AND THEN YOU MEET
A LOT OF PEOPLE
WITH DIFFERENT CULTURES,
DIFFERENT BACKGROUNDS.
WHEN YOU THOUGHT OF YOURSELF
BEING IN THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS,
IS THIS WHAT YOU THOUGHT
YOUR EMPIRE WOULD BE?
THIS IS WHAT I WAS
RAISED--IN THE DINER.
SO THIS IS SOMETHING
TO ME THAT--YEAH, YEAH.
FEELS NATURAL TO YOU.
YEAH, IT FEELS
VERY NATURAL.
FEELS THE SAME WAY
TO THE FOLKS
WHO JAM THE JOINT 24/7.
SOMETHING'S WRONG IF
THE TWO OF YOU AREN'T HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
(Guy) SO YOU KNOW
LATE-NIGHT DINERS,
AND YOU SAY THIS
STACKS ON TOP.
ABSOLUTELY.
NO QUESTIONS.
LOOK AT THE CROWD.
YOU KNOW THEY'VE BEEN COMIN'
HERE FOR YEARS.
THE JOINT IS PACKED
AT WHATEVER TIME IT IS.
SO WE'RE HAPPY.
WE'RE COMIN' BACK.
IN GREEK, TELL ME
"COME TO THE WHITE PALACE,
THE BEST FOOD YOU'LL
FIND 24/7."
(speaking Greek)
WOW, I THINK YOU THREW MORE
IN THERE THAN I GAVE YOU.
LITTLE BIT.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' TO PHILLY...
IT'S LIKE A SECOND HOME,
ISN'T IT?
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
WHERE THE SUN'S COMIN' UP ON
SOMETHING CALLED... SCRAPPLE?
IS IT MEAT?
IT'S MEAT.
IN A WORLD OF 24/7,
WHEN THE SUN'S COMIN' UP,
WELL, THAT MEANS THE END
OF A LATE NIGHT
OR THE BEGINNING
OF AN EARLY MORNING.
EITHER WAY YOU'RE
GONNA NEED SOME GRUB
AND THE FOLKS HERE AT THE DINING
CAR IN PHILADELPHIA,
WELL, THEY GOT YOU COVERED.
TURKEY, WHOLE WHEAT, MAYO.
THANK YOU.
VEAL PARMESAN?
MM-HMM.
I OFTEN HAVE THIS
IN THE MORNING.
CREAMED CHIPPED BEEF.
IT'S GOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE
EVERYTHING.
(Guy) THAT'S DELICIOUS.
LET ME SHOW YOU THIS
CHICKEN CAESAR.
COME ON WITH ME.
FIRST THING I THINK OF
IS WHAT AM I GONNA GET
AT THE DINER?
THAT'S A TOUGH CALL,
'CAUSE AT THIS JOINT,
THEY'VE GOT IT ALL...
THEY'RE ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
THEY'RE ALWAYS DIFFERENT.
AT ANY HOUR...
THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
WITH LOCAL FAVORITES
LIKE CHICKEN CROQUET...
IT'S VERY GOOD.
AND POT ROAST, REUBENS,
CINNAMON FRENCH TOAST,
EVEN HOMEMADE BAGELS.
IF WE HAD A NIGHT OUT, WE ALWAYS
STOPPED HERE FOR BREAKFAST.
YEARS AGO.
WOW, YOU GIRLS
ROLL HARD IN PHILLY.
THIS IS WHAT TIME I NORMALLY
ROLL IN FOR BREAKFAST.
WE HAD A LONG NIGHT
LAST NIGHT.
DID YOU?
WE DID.
IF A CUSTOMER WANTS TO EAT,
DAY OR NIGHT,
HE KNOWS HE CAN COME
TO THE DINING CAR.
JOE MOROZIN'S BEEN RUNNING
RESTAURANTS FOR YEARS.
HERE YOU ARE, LADIES.
HE BOUGHT THE ORIGINAL
DINING CAR 1N 1961,
AND ALMOST 20 YEARS LATER,
REPLACED IT
WITH A BIGGER ONE
RIGHT NEXT DOOR--
NOW RUN BY HIS THREE KIDS,
INCLUDING DAUGHTER NANCY.
A LOT OF THE CUSTOMERS CAME IN,
LIKE, 6:00 IN THE MORNING,
'CAUSE THEY WANTED
TO BE THE LAST ONE TO EAT
IN THE OLD DINER,
AND THE FIRST ONE TO EAT
IN THE NEW DINER.
SO HAVE YOU
BEEN HERE BEFORE?
OH, MY GOD,
EVERY SUNDAY.
WE COME EVERY SUNDAY.
EVERY SUNDAY?
TODAY'S NOT SUNDAY.
I KNOW.
TWO TIMES EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY--WEEKDAY.
FIVE DAYS A WEEK.
FIVE DAYS.
NOW HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
32 YEARS.
LONG ENOUGH
FOR CHEF LARRY THUM
TO KNOW EXACTLY WHAT FOLKS
AROUND HERE ARE LOOKIN' FOR,
LIKE THIS CLASSIC
FROM THE '40s.
(Guy) WHAT IS THAT?
CHIPPED BEEF.
IS IT CHIPPED BEEF?
MY DAD TALKED ABOUT IT
WHEN I WAS A KID,
ABOUT HAVIN' IT IN
THE MILITARY--
HAVIN' IT IN THE NAVY,
BUT THIS IS GONNA BE A FIRST.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN SOME OIL,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN THE FLOUR IN THE HOT OIL.
THIS IS LIKE A HOT PASTE.
GONNA BE LIKE NAPALM
IT GETS ON YOUR SKIN.
YOU'RE GONNA POUR THE HOT MILK
INTO THE ROUX,
AND THAT USUALLY THICKENS
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THAT'S DONE.
SO WHAT WAS THIS?
THIS WAS THE EYE OF THE ROUND?
THAT WAS ACTUALLY
A TOP ROUND.
OKAY, SO NOW WE
THIN-SLICE THIS?
(whistles)
THAT'S GOT
A LITTLE KICK.
RIGHT. CUT IT IN SQUARES--
LITTLE CUBES.
NOW REMEMBER,
WE'RE GONNA FRIZZLE IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT TO THE--
WE'RE GONNA WHAT IT UP?
WE'RE GONNA FRIZZLE IT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN A HOT PAN WITH OIL.
WE'RE GONNA SHA-NAZZLE?
IS THAT A COOKING TERM?
FRIZZLING?
YEAH, FRIZZLED BEEF.
SO THIS IS JUST GONNA
PUT A LITTLE CRISP ON IT?
YEP.
NOW WE'RE FRIZZLING.
CHEF McFRIZZEL.
AND PEOPLE ORDER THIS A LOT.
70, 80 GALLONS A WEEK.
YOU MAKE 20 OF
THOSE IN A WEEK.
SOMETIMES WHEN WE DO IT,
WHEN WE GET TOWARDS THE WEEKEND,
WE'LL MAKE A BIGGER BATCH.
YOU HAVE THAT SMOOTH
BLANDNESS OF THE SAUCE,
AND THEN YOU HAVE THE MEAT
THAT GIVES IT THE KICK.
YOU KNOW, THE OLD STANDBY
IS ALWAYS WHITE PASTE.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S THE BASIC FORMAT
RIGHT THERE.
MMM.
OH, THE TOAST MAKES IT.
I USED TO HEAR PEOPLE
COMPLAIN ABOUT THAT.
IT'S GOTTEN A BAD RAP,
BUT NOT WHEN IT'S MADE RIGHT.
NOT WHEN IT'S MADE HERE.
GET IT AWAY FROM ME
OR I'M GONNA EAT IT ALL.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
AROUND HERE,
IT'S STILL A FAVORITE,
AND SO'S THIS LOCAL FLAVOR.
W-WHAT'S THAT?
(waitress)
THAT IS SCRAPPLE.
IS IT MEAT?
IT'S MEAT.
ACTUALLY, IT'S DEEP-FRIED
PORK SCRAPS IN CORNMEAL.
THE LOCALS LOVE TO TALK YOU
INTO TRYING IT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE SURPRISED.
I WAS BORN
AND RAISED ON IT.
THAT'S FUNKADELLIC, MAN.
DO YOU EAT IT?
I LOVE IT.
SO BAD FOR YOU,
BUT IT TASTES SO, SO GOOD.
TODAY IS YOUR BIRTHDAY?
YES.
HOW 'BOUT A PIECE
OF SCRAPPLE à LA MODE?
AND IT ISN'T JUST THE SCRAPPLE.
AT THIS JOINT,
THEY'RE TOTALLY ON TOP
OF ALL THE LOCAL FLAVORS.
REMINDS ME EXACTLY OF WHAT I
USED TO HAVE WHEN I WAS LITTLE.
CHICKEN CROQUETTES
WE CALL THIS.
"CROQUETTES?"
IT'S A VERY OLD
TRADITIONAL DINER ITEM.
PEOPLE YEARS AGO,
THEY WOULD TAKE THEIR SCRAPS
FROM THE CHICKEN, ROLL IT UP,
BREAD IT AND FRY IT UP,
AND GET AN EXTRA MEAL
OUT OF IT.
SO IT'S MAKING, LIKE,
A LITTLE CHICKEN
AND DOUGH DUMPLING.
WE JUST USE CRACKER MEAL.
WE USE A MILK EGG WASH
AND WE USE BREADCRUMBS.
SO NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
GO FRY THESE?
GONNA FRY 'EM UP.
THESE GO DOWN, BUT THEY
GOTTA BE MADE IN CONES.
THE TRADITIONAL DINER
ONE THAT'S AROUND HERE
IS USUALLY MADE IN A CONE.
PLACE 'EM ON A BED
OF MASHED POTATOES, SAUCE 'EM.
SO MILK OF CHICKEN STOCK
AND PARSLEY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HOT, I BET.
LOOKS LIKE A VOLCANO.
BRO, THAT IS RICH AND BIG.
THE SAUCE BRINGS IT HOME.
IT'S A FILLING, FILLING MEAL.
YES.
IT'S, YOU KNOW,
ONE OF THOSE COMFORT FOODS.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK, THIS
PLACE IS TAKING COMFORT FOOD
TO A WHOLE NEW PLACE.
WELL, WE DON'T MAKE "CREPES"
WE MAKE "CRAPES"
IN PHILADELPHIA.
THE DINING CAR IN PHILLY
IS ALL ABOUT COMFORT FOOD...
ONE GRILLED CHEESE,
COMIN' AT YOU.
24/7.
WHO'S THE COOK,
KING KONG?
BUT COMFORT FOOD AT THIS JOINT
IS MORE THAN JUST THE BASICS.
CREPES FLORENTINE.
IT'S ONE OF THEIR
SPECIALTIES HERE.
THIS IS ONE OF THE FIRST MENUS
THAT WE'VE EVER COME ACROSS
THAT WE'VE
SEEN "CREPES."
OR CRêPES.
HOW DO YOU SAY IT?
"CREPES?"
WELL, WE DON'T MAKE "CREPES."
WE MAKE "CRAPES"
IN PHILADELPHIA.
WHAT DID PEOPLE THINK?
I MEAN, YOU'RE IN A DINER.
IT STARTED OUT SLOW, BUT THEN
IT STARTED TO CATCH ON
A LITTLE BIT AT A TIME.
WELL, LET'S GET
OUR "CRAPE" ON.
YOU START WITH SIX EGGS
AND SIX EXTRA YOLKS.
RIGHT.
3 CUPS OF FLOUR.
EXACTLY 3 CUPS OF FLOUR.
EXACTLY 3 CUPS.
SEE THAT EAGLE EYE?
GOOD EYE.
SO ON THE CREPES THIS IS
CALLED SUPREME SAUCE?
THAT'S CORRECT.
OKAY, SO CHICKEN STOCK GOIN'
INTO SOME BLOND ROUX,
SO THAT'S GONNA TIGHTEN UP AND
MAKE, LIKE, A CHICKEN GRAVY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SAUTé UP A LITTLE BIT
OF MUSHROOMS.
NOW THIS IS NOT
TRADITIONAL DINER FARE.
ONE OF OUR PHILOSOPHIES
IS WHEN PEOPLE COME IN,
WE HAVE A LITTLE
BIT FOR EVERYBODY.
COLD CREPE BATTER.
HOT PANS.
LITTLE CLARIFIED BUTTER.
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
I'D RATHER HAVE A LITTLE
EXTRA BUTTER IN 'EM,
AND YOU'RE GONNA PUT IN TWO
LADLEFULS OF CREPE BATTER.
WITH THAT MUCH BUTTER, I'M
A LITTLE GNARLY ABOUT FLIPPIN'.
I MEAN, I DIDN'T...
YOU BRING IT UP AND OVER.
NOW TRY IT.
YEAH, NO.
WANT AN APRON?
READY?
WONDERFUL! THAT'S
A NICE-LOOKIN' OMELET THERE.
THIS IS CRAZY CREPE!
IT'S CRAZY CREPE!
NOW WHAT?
SLICED HAM.
NOW WHAT--THIS HAM.
WHAT DOES THIS TASTE LIKE?
THIS IS--I THINK IT'S BAKED.
SMOKED.
VIRGINIA BAKED HAM.
I COULD HAVE 6 OR
12 POUNDS OF THAT.
NATURAL CURE
CHEDDAR CHEESE.
FRESH-COOKED SPINACH.
I'M JUST GONNA ROLL 'EM UP.
THIS IS HOW WE ROLL
SUSHI, TOO.
THEN WE'LL JUST GIVE 'EM
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT.
YOU'RE JUST TEASIN'
ME WITH THAT.
THAT'S ALL.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
YOU'RE TEASIN' ME.
MMM!
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THE--THE KICKER
IS THAT SUPREME SAUCE.
MMM.
WE TRIED TO TAKE CREPES AND
MAKE COMFORT FOOD OUT OF 'EM.
WELCOME TO COMFORT CREPE.
AND THE REAL COMFORT
FOR FOLKS AROUND HERE
IS KNOWIN' THEY
CAN COUNT ON THIS JOINT
24/7.
(man) OH, THE FOOD'S
ALWAYS BEEN GOOD,
AND YOU CAN ALWAYS
COUNT ON IT BEING GOOD.
THIS DINER HERE'S
GONNA TAKE CARE OF YA.
THEY KNOW ME, AND THAT
MAKES IT NICE, YOU KNOW?
YOU FEEL COMFORTABLE HERE.
I'M HERE ALL THE TIME.
GONNA GET WHATEVER YOU WANT
WHENEVER YOU NEED IT.
RIGHT.
HANGIN' IN THERE.
YEAH, NOT BAD.
NO, NOT BAD. SO WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO NOW? GO TO SLEEP?
OH, MY GOD, YES.
YEAH, BACK TO BED.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
UH, HERE AT THE SPA
OF THE DINER CAR...
PLEASE TELL ME,
AS I CUKE MY EYES,
WHAT, UH--