HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DID YOU SEND ME AN E-MAIL?
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
VIEWER'S CHOICE.
YOU ARE THE REASON
I AM HERE.
THE 56-YEAR-OLD
FLORIDA LEGEND...
WHENEVER YOU DRIVE BY, THERE'S
ALWAYS A TON OF PEOPLE HERE.
WHERE THE SEAFOOD IS SMOKIN'.
THAT'S TASTY.
AND THEY'VE GOT
A WHOLE NOTHER TAKE
ON SURF AND TURF...
(man) EAT
THE FISH SPREAD
AND THEN YOU EAT
THE HAMBURGER.
THAT'S THE SURF
AND TURF.
THE JOINT NEAR SEATTLE WHERE
IT'S TOTALLY HAWAIIAN...
THE COOK IT
LIKE THEY COOK IT IN HAWAII.
FROM THE PORK
YOU GET AT A LUAU...
THAT'S TENDER, MAN.
TO A TRUE HAWAIIAN CLASSIC...
IT'S RICE AND SPAM.
LIKE A HAWAIIAN
HAMBURGER.
AND THE MINNESOTA TIKI BAR
WHERE THEY'RE PUTTING RUM
RAISINS ON PIZZA...
LIKE HOT LITTLE CAPSULES
OF JUICE.
CANDY BARS IN THE DEEP FRYER,
BEER BATTER ON SOMETHING
CALLED A CHEESE CURD...
YOU BREAD IT. YOU DEEP-FRY IT.
THEY TASTE GREAT.
AND THE DRINKS ARE ON FIRE.
MY HAIR IS FLAMMABLE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'M HERE CRUISIN' THE BEACH AREA
IN ST. PETERSBURG, FLORIDA
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF TAMPA.
NOW THE REASON I'M HERE
IS BECAUSE SO MANY OF YOU
HAVE E-MAILED ME TELLIN' ME
ABOUT THIS JOINT
I JUST GOTTA CHECK OUT.
TED PETERS FAMOUS SMOKED FISH.
NICE CALL.
CAN'T YOU SMELL IT?
THE SMOKEHOUSE OVER THERE.
(woman) THE VERY
FIRST TIME WE CAME,
HE BOUGHT ME ONE OF THOSE
SMOKED MACKEREL PIECES.
ROMANTIC.
THE SALMON IS SO GOOD.
GRAB A FORK.
MMM.
I'VE PUT ON 30 POUNDS
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE.
...THANKS TO THE E-MAILERS
WHO GOT ME DOWN HERE...
YOU CAN JUST SIT BACK,
RELAX, ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
LIKE LAURA BLACK...
HOW LONG YOU
BEEN COMIN' HERE?
ABOUT 10 YEARS.
AND GEORGE DAVIS.
MY GRANDMOTHER AND FATHER
BROUGHT ME HERE.
MY DAUGHTERS--MY KIDS,
I BROUGHT THEM HERE.
NOW THE GRANDKIDS.
THIS IS, LIKE, FIFTH GENERATION.
THE PLACE ITSELF HAS BEEN
FAMILY RUN FOR 56 YEARS.
CO-OWNER MICHAEL LATHROP'S
UNCLE
WAS THE GUY WITH
HIS NAME ON THE SIGN
AND THE GOOD IDEA
TO TURN A BACKYARD HOBBY,
SMOKING FISH,
INTO A BUSINESS.
YEAH, TED PETERS.
HE TOOK IT FROM THE BACKYARD,
STUCK IT OUT
IN THE FRONT YARD
AND KINDA WAVED THE TRAFFIC
DOWN AS IT WOULD GO BY.
PEOPLE WOULD PUT
THE BRAKES ON, BACK UP,
AND SAY, "WHAT'S
THAT ABOUT?"
TODAY FOLKS ARE STILL
JAMMIN' ON THE BRAKES
FOR SMOKED SALMON, MAHIMAHI
AND THE HOMETOWN FAVORITE,
MULLET.
IN HERE THROUGH
THE JOHN WAYNE DOORS?
STILL MADE THE SAME WAY,
BY THE SAME FAMILY.
THIS IS OUR FISHMONGER
FOR THE DAY?
BEN, HE'S FIFTH
GENERATION HERE.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
THAT'S LIKE A PIECE OF HISTORY.
JUST SHOOK
THE LIBERTY BELL.
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA DO
IS JUST RUN SOME SALT--
LIGHT--
OVER ALL THE FISH.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT OUR
MIXTURE ON ALL OF 'EM.
AND WHAT IS THE--
WHAT IS THE MIXTURE?
THE SECRET SAUCE.
WELL, YOU GOTTA GIVE ME
A BASIS OF IT.
ARE WE TOMATO-BASED IN HERE?
I CAN SEE OIL IN IT.
YEAH, TOMATO-BASED.
BUT YOU'RE NOT STIRRING IT UP.
YOU'RE NOT PUTTIN' A LOT ON.
NO, IT'S REAL LIGHT,
JUST TO KEEP IT FROM BURNING--
GIVE IT A LITTLE COLOR.
JUST PICK UP
THE WHOLE TRAY HERE.
JUST SLIDE IT IN THE CART AND
TAKE IT OVER TO THE SMOKEHOUSE.
I'VE NEVER TAKEN MY SMOKED
FISH FOR A WALK BEFORE.
JUST TAKE THE TRAY
AND SLIDE IT IN THERE.
SO...
I'D GUESS THAT YOU ONLY--
YOU HAVE TO BE A FAMILY MEMBER
OR YOU'D HAVE TO HAVE
THE EAGLE-SPAN REACH.
DID YOU SEE THAT?
YEAH, LITTLE GUYS
DON'T DO THIS WELL.
WHAT ARE WE SMOKIN' WITH?
JUST RED OAK.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
IN A FEW MINUTES--
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
SUCH A CONCENTRATION
OF SMOKE IN THERE
THAT IT'S GONNA BE EQUALLY
SEEPING OUT OF ALL THE TRAYS.
DO THEY GO IN IN A CERTAIN
LOCATION TO START WITH?
YEAH, YOU WANT THE RAW FISH
ON THE BOTTOM
AND AS YOU ADD, YOU RAISE UP.
YOU DON'T JUST SET
IT AND FORGET IT.
YOU ACTUALLY HAVE TO BE
PARTICIPATING EVERY 15 MINUTES,
PULLIN' THE RACK,
LOOKIN' WHERE YOU'RE AT,
SEEIN' HOW THINGS
ARE MOVIN' ALONG.
YOU GUYS EVER HEARD ABOUT
SECONDHAND SMOKE?
NEXT UP, THE COOLING CABINET,
AND THEY'RE READY TO SERVE.
THEY GOT THE BEST SMOKED FISH
THERE IS AROUND.
AND NOW THEY HAVE SALMON,
WHICH IS UNBELIEVABLE.
SMOKED MULLET'S
REALLY GOOD, TOO.
THAT IS TASTY.
HOW WOULD HAVE THUNK?
AND WHO'D HAVE
THUNK UP THIS ONE?
IT'S A TOP SELLER--
SMOKED FISH ALL CHOPPED UP
INTO TED PETERS'
LEGENDARY FISH SPREAD.
BE SURE AND ORDER
THE FISH SPREAD.
I HEAR OUT OF EVERYTHING
AT TED PETERS,
THIS IS, LIKE--THE SPREAD
IS, LIKE, THE KICKER.
THIS IS THE THING.
SO WHAT IS MADE IN
THE FISH SPREAD?
THAT IS MAHI
AND MULLET.
THE MULLET IS THE KICKER
TO THE SPREAD, THOUGH.
THE--
YOU CAN'T USE MY W--
I'M THE KIC---
THAT'S MY WORD!
I WONDERED WHERE
I HEARD IT FROM.
OKAY, SO YOU BREAK
IT DOWN BY HAND,
THEN IT GOES INTO THE GRINDER
TO MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S UNIFORM SIZE.
EXACTLY.
SO WHAT YOU WANT TO DO,
YOU WANT TO GET IT
AS FLUFFY AS YOU CAN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
CELERY AND ONIONS.
CELERY AND ONION.
PICKLE RELISH.
SWEET RELISH.
YOU'RE GONNA MIX 'EM AGAIN.
IT'S ALWAYS BY HAND?
IT'S ALWAYS BY HAND.
OKAY, NOW
THE SALAD DRESSING.
IT HOLDS IT TOGETHER.
THIS DEFINITELY YOU GOTTA HAVE
SHOULDER MUSCLES FOR.
LOOK AT YOU, MAN.
YOU ARE A MACHINE.
♪♪
WHAT PULLS
THAT ALL TOGETHER--
ONION, THE CELERY
AND THE SMOKE.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD,
ACTUALLY.
YOU CAN GET THE FISH SPREAD
ON A SANDWICH
BUT LOT OF FOLKS GET IT
AS PART OF A MEAL
LOCALS KNOW AS...
THE TED PETERS
SURF AND TURF.
YOU EAT THE FISH SPREAD
AND THEN THAT'S THE FISH,
AND THEN YOU EAT
THE HAMBURGER.
THAT'S THE SURF
AND TURF.
THEIR CHEESEBURGERS
ARE GREAT.
(Guy) WHAT KIND
OF CHEESE?
SWISS, AMERICAN--
VELVEETA.
THAT'S A REAL BURGER.
THAT IS.
THE CHEESE--
IT ALWAYS STAYS MELTED.
SO IT'S ALWAYS, LIKE,
EXTRA GOOEY.
BESIDES, WHERE ELSE
CAN YOU EAT ON PLATES
THAT REMIND YOU OF YOUR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CAFETERIA?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
AND TO ROUND OUT THE TOTAL
TED PETERS EXPERIENCE,
THE LOCALS HAVE ONE MORE
SUGGESTION.
BE SURE AND GET
THE WARM POTATO SALAD.
AND THEN WE TAKE THE BACON.
WHOA. WHOA. WHOA. WHOA.
HOT GREASE AND ALL?
YES.
MMM, THAT IS UP THERE
IN THE TOP BEST POTATO
SALADS I'VE EVER HAD.
FITS RIGHT IN
WITH THE SURF AND TURF
AND THE SMOKED MULLET...
I LOVE SMOKED MULLET.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING ELSE
HERE, TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
AND THE WHOLE TED PETERS THING
THAT FOLKS AROUND HERE
HAVE BEEN COMING BACK FOR
SINCE 1951.
I HAD MY FIRST SMOKED MULLET
ABOUT 30 YEARS AGO
AT THIS PLACE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN COMIN' HERE?
25 YEARS.
WERE YOU IN A STROLLER?
YES.
SO MANY PEOPLE LOOK AT US
AS NOT THE OWNERS,
BUT THE CARETAKERS OF SOMETHING
THAT'S PART THEIRS,
BECAUSE THIS RESTAURANT
IN THIS AREA
IS THE LAST THING THAT ANCHORS
THEIR CHILDHOOD MEMORIES.
DID YOU THINK THAT SENDING IN
AN E-MAIL TO FOOD NETWORK
FOR "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" WAS GONNA
TURN INTO THIS?
I NEED TO STOP SITTING UP
AT 2:00 IN THE MORNING
HALF ASLEEP AND TAPPING
ON THE KEYBOARD.
I GOTTA SAY THANKS, MAN,
AND I HAVE TO ASK YOU
AND TELL EVERYBODY ELSE
TO WRITE IN
AND TELL US YOUR
RECOMMENDATIONS.
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
WILL GO WHERE YOU RECOMMEND.
RIGHT?
THEY WILL.
BE CAREFUL, THEY'LL SHOW UP.
COMIN' UP, YOU'RE SENDING ME
TO A JOINT NEAR SEATTLE
WHERE IT MIGHT
AS WELL BE HAWAII...
THE COOK IT
LIKE THEY COOK IT IN HAWAII.
YOU GOT A PALM TREE?
BANANA LEAF.
AND FOLKS ARE PACKIN'
IN FOR SPAM
WRAPPED IN SEAWEED.
MMM, LIKE A HAWAIIAN
HAMBURGER.
WELL, Y'ALL DID IT TO ME AGAIN.
YOU SEND IN YOUR E-MAILS AND
YOUR RECOMMENDATIONS
OF YOUR FAVORITE JOINTS.
THIS TIME, I CAME BACK ACROSS
THE COUNTRY TO MY COAST,
THE WEST COAST,
OUTSIDE OF SEATTLE
TO A PLACE THAT'S AS TRUE TO ITS
FAMILY'S ORIGIN IN FOOD
AS IT IS IN MUSIC.
(cheering)
IT'S A NONSTOP PARTY
AT BOBBY'S HAWAIIAN STYLE
RESTAURANT.
THIS IS BOBBY.
I WANT TO THANK ALL
OF YOU FOR COMING HERE.
THIS IS THE MUSIC
HE GREW UP WITH,
AND THIS IS THE FOOD
HE GREW UP WITH.
YOU GOT A PALM TREE?
BANANA LEAF.
A BANANA LEAF.
THEY COOK IT LIKE
THEY COOK IT IN HAWAII.
FROM THE PORK YOU'D
GET AT A LUAU
TO ISLAND-STYLE BARBECUE,
AND SALT-CURED SALMON.
OH, IT TASTES JUST LIKE HAWAII.
BECAUSE OWNER BOBBY NAKIHEI
WAS BORN AND RAISED THERE...
WHAT ISLAND DID
YOU LIVE ON?
MOLOKAI.
MO-KALI?
NO, MO-LO-KA-I.
MO-LO-KA-I.
HE'S LAUGHIN'
BACK THERE.
WHERE HE LEARNED TO COOK
FROM FAMILY, FRIENDS
AND JUST ABOUT EVERYONE ELSE.
WHEN SOMEBODY WOULD
THROW A PARTY OR A LUAU
OR A WHATEVER--
I WAS THERE.
TILL HE WAS HERE.
YOU SEE, BOBBY
AND HIS WIFE DIANA
MOVED TO WASHINGTON STATE
IN '89.
HE KEPT COOKING AS A HOBBY,
AND SEVEN YEARS AGO,
DECIDED TO TAKE A CHANCE
AND OPENED A RESTAURANT
IN EVERETT,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF SEATTLE.
PEOPLE WERE LOOKING AT US LIKE,
"ARE YOU CRAZY?
IN THE MIDDLE OF EVERETT?
WHAT'S UP, BOB?
HOW YOU DOIN'?
THEY'RE LOOKIN'
PRETTY SANE ABOUT NOW.
WITH A CONSTANT CROWD OF
TRANSPLANTED ISLANDERS...
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
AND APPRECIATIVE LOCALS.
EAT IT ALL?
YEP.
YOU DID?
VINCENT ABELLA SAID
THE REASON HE E-MAILED
TO GET ME TO COME HERE
WAS SIMPLE.
I HAVE TO TALK TO YOU,
BUDDY.
BOBBY'S FOOD IS THE BOMB,
AND PEOPLE OUGHTA KNOW.
PEOPLE THINK IT'S JUST,
YOU KNOW,
PLASTIC LUAUS AND ALL
OF THAT TYPE OF THING.
THIS IS REALLY HAWAIIAN FOOD.
THIS IS ABOUT
THE REAL DEAL.
YEP.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MOST FAMOUS
HAWAIIAN DISH OF ALL--
KALUA PIG.
YOU DON'T HAVE THE KALUA PIG,
IT'S NOT A LUAU.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL GO HOME.
SO WHAT DO WE START WITH?
A LITTLE PORK BUTT?
PORK BUTT,
AND I'M GONNA SEASON IT.
OH, LET ME GUESS.
HAWAIIAN SALT.
HAWAIIAN SALT,
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
A KOSHER SALT.
THE WAVES CRASH
ONTO A ROCK,
AND THEN DRY UP--
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
THAT'S WHAT THAT IS.
YEAH.
NOW WHAT IS THIS?
YOU GOT A PALM TREE?
BANANA LEAF.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
AND NOW ALL I'M GONNA DO
IS JUST COVER IT
WITH BANANA LEAVES.
YOU'RE GONNA USE
THE INTERNAL MOISTURE.
IT'S GONNA RENDER DOWN 'CAUSE
OF THE FAT AND THE MOISTURE.
OKAY, HOW LONG WILL
WE COOK IT?
AT LEAST EIGHT
TO TEN HOURS.
REALLY?
AT WHAT TEMPERATURE?
AT ABOUT 250.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S SOFT.
IT JUST TEARS APART.
THAT'S TENDER, MAN.
YEAH.
IT REALLY REMINDS ME
OF PULLED PORK
JUST WITHOUT THE SMOKE.
WITHOUT THE SMOKE, YEAH.
YOU GET A LITTLE HINT...
OF THE--
OF THE BANANA LEAF.
YEAH.
GIVES A LITTLE TROPICAL
NOSE TO IT.
IT'S NOT JUST PLAIN,
OLD PORK.
THAT'S TASTY.
IF THE KALUA PORK IS YOUR INTRO
TO HAWAIIAN FOOD,
YOUR NEXT STEP IS
SOMETHING CALLED LAULAU.
(Bobby) CUT IT UP INTO
SMALL LITTLE CHUNKS.
CUBED PORK IN A DIFFERENT
TROPICAL WRAPPER.
WHAT ARE THESE?
THESE ARE TARO LEAVES.
THESE COME FROM HAWAII?
YES, JUST PUT IT IN.
AFTER THIS ONE'S STEAMED
IN A PRESSURE COOKER...
WHOA, LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH.
THE LEAF IS PART OF THE MEAL.
THEY EAT THE LEAF?
YEAH.
NICE AND TENDER.
STRONG LEAF.
YEAH.
LIKE WHEN YOU STEW A MEAT.
MM-HMM.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT
OF VEGETABLES IN THERE.
YEAH.
IT'S GOOD.
DIFFERENT.
AND DIFFERENT'S BEEN
CATCHIN' ON AROUND HERE...
(Guy) THAT'S A BIG SLURP YOU
MAKE WHEN YOU EAT THAT.
HOOKIN' A LOT OF FOLKS
WHO DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT THEY'VE BEEN MISSIN'
FROM 2,600 MILES AWAY.
HOW LONG'S MICHAELA
BEEN COMIN' HERE?
SINCE SHE'S BEEN BORN.
SHE'S BEEN COMIN'
ABOUT 2 1/2 YEARS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THEY
WOULD BE MOST SURPRISED
OR MOST INTRIGUED TO LEARN
ABOUT HAWAIIAN FOOD?
I THINK THE SIMPLICITY OF
PREPARING THE FOOD.
LIKE SOMETHING CALLED
LOMI LOMI SALMON,
KIND OF LIKE A RAW
SALMON CEVICHE.
LOMI LOMI IN HAWAIIAN
MEANS TO MIX.
IN ENGLISH,
IT MEANS TO MIX.
THIS IS TRADITIONAL,
TRADITIONAL HAWAIIAN.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME SALMON.
SO THIS HAS GOT, LIKE,
A LITTLE SALT CURE.
YEAH, CURE, YEAH.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
TOMATOES--DICED TOMATOES.
I'M GONNA ADD THE ONIONS AND
NOW I'M GONNA ADD SOME, UH...
SOME GREEN ONIONS?
GREEN ONIONS.
AND SO NOW I'M JUST GONNA
ADD SOME HAWAIIAN SALT
AND JUST MIX IT.
NO SAUCE?
NO, IT'S JUST--
IT'S LIKE A SALSA
WITHOUT A SAUCE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
MMM, THAT'S TASTY.
YEAH?
LOMI LOMI.
MIXI-MIXI.
BUT THE ULTIMATE
HAWAIIAN MIXI-MIXI
IS SOMETHING
CALLED SPAM MUSUBI--
HALF-SUSHI, HALF-SPAM.
(Bobby) BACK IN
THE WAR DAYS,
THAT WAS THE CHEAPEST THING
TO GET IN THE MARKET.
BUT IT WOULD LAST.
IT WOULD WORK.
SO THEN IT BECOMES DEVELOPED
INTO THE--THE MENU,
INTO THE DIET, INTO THE IDEA
OF THE COOKING STYLE
OF THE ISLANDERS.
YEAH.
AND THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
RIGHT AFTER WE'RE DONE
FAST-FRYING IT,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
OVER TO THE GRILL
WHERE I ADD MY SAUCE.
SO YOU CAN'T TELL ME
WHAT'S IN THE SECRET SAUCE?
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
I LIKE WHAT
I GOT IN THERE.
I THINK I GOT A LITTLE GINGER,
A LITTLE HONEY, A LITTLE SOY.
CLOSE.
AND THEN WRAPPED WITH RICE
AND SHEETS OF PRESSED SEAWEED
CALLED NORI.
LOOK AT HOW THE CONTAINER
FITS EXACTLY.
PUSH IT DOWN.
ALL THE WAY OUT?
ALL THE WAY OUT.
WE JUST GONNA FLAP
ONE SIDE OVER.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
MUSUBI.
MMM, LIKE A HAWAIIAN
HAMBURGER.
...WRAPPED IN SEAWEED
AND IT'S JUST A REAL GOOD TREAT.
LIKE THE PLACE ITSELF.
FOR SOME, IT'S A TASTE OF HOME.
FOR OTHERS, IT'S A DIFFERENT
KIND OF HOME COOKIN'.
OH, THANK YOU! OH, YOU'RE
GONNA GIVE ME ANOTHER ONE.
OH, AND I GET
A THIRD ONE!
WITH IS PASSION AND JUST
DOING IT HIS WAY,
WE STAYED AUTHENTIC.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT YOU
WOULD FIND BACK HOME.
HIDDEN AWAY,
NOT FAR FROM SEATTLE.
ANOTHER GREAT JOINT WE FOUND
BECAUSE YOU E-MAILED
AND TOLD ME TO STOP IN...
OH, I LIKE THAT.
KEEP PUTTIN' 'EM ON.
AND CHECK IT OUT.
I'M GLAD YOU CAME.
YOU'RE AWESOME, MAN.
THANKS, MAN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
UP NEXT, YOU'RE SENDING
ME TO MINNESOTA
TO CHECK OUT THE TATTOOS,
TATER TOTS...
LOOK AT THIS GUY. IS HE
IN THE HOSPITALITY BUSINESS?
RUM RAISIN PIZZA...
THAT'S REALLY GOOD PIE
AND SOMETHING CALLED
CHEESE CURDS.
BATTER IS MONEY.
I DIG FUNKY JOINTS
THAT HAVE FUNKY NAMES
'CAUSE IT USUALLY MEANS
THEY SERVE FUNKY FOOD.
SO I THINK I MAY HAVE FOUND
MY NEW MINNEAPOLIS HANGOUT--
PSYCHO SUZI'S MOTOR LOUNGE.
(man) COMAS UP.
CHEERS.
A ONE-OF-A-KIND TIKI LOUNGE...
A LOCAL GUY
MADE THIS FOR US.
TIKI--AWESOME.
AN EXPERIENCE I WAS TOLD
I GOTTA CHECK OUT
IN AN E-MAIL
FROM VIEWER CINDI MAXHAM.
THEY'RE, LIKE,
CLASSY TRASHY.
YES.
AND WHEN I CAME IN, I WAS LIKE,
OOH, I'M ON VACATION!
IT'S KIND OF A LITTLE TROPICAL
PARADISE IN THE CITY.
WITH ONE OF THE MOST
OUT-OF-BOUNDS MENUS...
SANDWICH TOTS.
FOLKS HAVE EVER
FALLEN IN LOVE WITH.
MINI MAC ROLLS.
(bell dings)
I'VE NEVER HAD
A POTLUCK PICKLE ROLLUP.
PICKLE ROLLUPS
ON THE FLY.
SALAMI WITH
CREAM CHEESE,
AND THEN IT'S JUST WRAPPED
AROUND A PICKLE AND SLICED UP.
WHICH IS SOMETHING I'VE HAD
SINCE I WAS, LIKE, A LITTLE KID,
AND I DON'T FIND THEM IN MANY
PLACES EXCEPT FOR HERE.
DEVILLED EGGS--YOU DON'T SEE
THOSE ON EVERY MENU.
YEAH.
ARE THOSE TATER TOTS?
THOSE ARE. WOULD YOU
LIKE A TATER TOT?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
LOOK AT THIS GUY.
IS HE IN THE HOSPITALITY
BUSINESS?
THEY'VE GOT TOTALLY
CUSTOM PIZZAS...
START THE MIDDLE ON FIRE.
FLAMING TIKI DRINKS...
MY HAIR IS FLAMMABLE.
AND DEEP-FRIED EVERYTHING.
BEER-BATTERED ASPARAGUS.
TASTY.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S KINDA RETRO.
KINDA DIFFERENT.
AND IT'S ALL COMIN' FROM
THE MIND OF OWNER LESLIE BOCK.
I'M A RULE BREAKER.
REBEL.
I SEE THAT.
A CLOTHING DESIGNER-TURNED-
TATTOO PARLOR OWNER...
I DON'T KNOW THAT I HAVE ENOUGH
TATTOOS TO BE ON THE TEAM.
I DON'T THINK YOU DO.
TURNED RESTAURATEUR.
(Leslie) I DECIDED I NEEDED
A RESTAURANT AND A BAR,
JUST TO MIX IT UP.
MAKES A LOT OF SENSE.
GOOD.
SO FOUR YEARS AGO,
SHE SNAPPED UP
THIS OLD A&W DRIVE-IN
AND TURNED IT TIKI.
I'M NOT KNOWN FOR BEING
A SUPER-SENSIBLE PERSON.
I MEAN, IT ALL MADE
SENSE IN MY HEAD.
(Guy) YOU'RE NOT FROM
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
NO.
DID YOU GET
ANY TRAINING?
AFTER.
PICK SOMETHING.
WHAT SELLS THE MOST
OF ALL THE FOOD?
UM, ANYTHING BEER-BATTERED
OR THE PIZZA.
WE'LL START WITH
THE BEER BATTER.
PUT SOME FLOUR IN.
BAKING SODA.
SALT.
THEN WE GOT OUR EGGS.
AND THEN WE DUMP.
THEN SOME PABST BLUE RIBBON.
IS IT PBR?
YES.
OH, I LOVE PBR.
GOES GREAT ON SOMETHING
CALLED A CHEESE CURD.
FOLKS HERE SAY
THEY'RE A STATE FAIR FAVORITE.
IT'S A LITTLE NUGGET OF CHEESE.
HAVE YOU SEEN, UH,
A CHEESE CURD BEFORE?
YEAH.
YOU LAUGH.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF 'EM.
YOU BREAD IT.
YOU DEEP-FRY IT.
THEY TASTE GREAT.
JUST LIKE CHEESE CURDS. I DON'T
KNOW WHAT ELSE TO TELL YOU.
THIS IS A CURD?
THEY'RE FROM WISCONSIN.
IT'S ACTUALLY WHITE CHEDDAR.
IN THE BEER BATTER.
DROP. DROP. DROP.
WE LIKE 'EM GOLDEN-BROWN.
BATTER'S MONEY.
CURD'S NICE AND CHEWY.
TASTES LIKE, UH--
LIKE MOZZARELLA?
IT DOES TASTE LIKE MOZZARELLA.
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
BUT IT'S WHITE CHEDDAR.
LIAR!
THE BEST CHEESE CURDS
I'VE EVER HAD.
AND THE DEEP-FRYING DOESN'T
STOP WITH CHEESE.
THOSE ARE RED ROCKETS.
YOU LIKE THE RED ROCKETS?
I LOVE THE RED ROCKETS.
RED ROCKET--BEER-BATTERED
MINI WIENERS.
HAND-DIPPED.
COMES WITH MUSTARD.
THEY'RE GOOD.
I DO TWO AT A TIME.
REALLY A HARD TECHNIQUE.
HOW MANY COME
WITH AN ORDER?
20.
20?
OH, THANKS FOR HELPING.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
HOT!
SO THEY'RE DONE.
THOSE ARE TASTY.
I BET YOU THOSE WOULDN'T
GO ALONG GREAT
WITH A BIG, OLD,
HUGE PITCHER OF BEER.
BET YOU THOSE WOULDN'T
GO ALONG GREAT
WITH A BIG, OLD, HUGE
PITCHER OF BEER.
CAN I GET YOU
A PITCHER OF BEER?
THAT'S A GOOD IDEA!
SHE'S ALSO FRYING UP
ONION RINGS,
HOT WINGS, EVEN SNICKERS BARS
AND SOMETHING CALLED
A MINI MEX ROLL.
WHERE DID THIS COME FROM?
CAME OUTTA NOWHERE.
WHAT KIND OF CHEESE?
PEPPER JACK.
AND THEN SOME ROASTED
RED PEPPERS.
WOW, THAT'S A LOT
OF JALAPEÑOS.
YEAH, WE LIKE THINGS,
YOU KNOW, A LITTLE ZIPPY.
AND THEN WE ADD
SOME CORN.
AND SOME BLACK BEANS.
AND, UM,
SOME SCALLIONS.
AND THEN WE STIR.
MM-KAY.
SO THEN WE ADD OUR
CHICKEN MIXTURE.
THE TACO-SEASONED--
CHICKEN STUFF.
BLEND.
MIX?
MIX.
WE USE WONTON WRAPPERS.
THEN WE FRY.
WE USUALLY PULL THEM OUT
WHEN THEY'RE FLOATING.
MMM.
THAT'S TASTY.
THANK YOU, GUY.
THAT'S CRAZY TASTY.
EVERYTHING.
IT'S GREAT FOOD.
AND I LIKE THE TIKI STYLE.
AND ALL OF THE TIKI CUPS
THAT ARE UP THERE?
I WENT TO TIKI CONVENTIONS.
THERE'S A TIKI CONVENTION?
YES.
AND AS LONG AS
YOU GOT THE CUPS...
I LOVE THE DRINKS.
GIN AND TEQUILA.
SOME VODKA
AND SOME TRIPLE SEC.
SOME RUM.
SO THERE'S ONLY FIVE SHOTS.
WELL, HOLD ON.
WE'RE NOT DONE YET.
YEAH.
SOME MANGO. SOME ORANGE
AND PINEAPPLE IN THERE.
FLOAT A LITTLE DARK RUM.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
OFF WITH SOME 151.
THERE YOU GO.
START THE MIDDLE
ON FIRE
AND ENJOY.
MMM. PHEW!
THAT'S TASTY.
AND THE RUM DOESN'T STOP
WITH THE DRINKS.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
CHECK OUT THE PIZZA.
WITH RUM-SOAKED RAISINS?
THAT'S GOOD PIE.
AT PSYCHO SUZI'S
IN MINNEAPOLIS,
THEY'RE SERVING UP
CHEESE CURDS...
I LOVE THE CHEESE CURDS.
TATER TOTS...
NOTHING BETTER
THAN A TOT.
DEEP-FRIED MINI DOGS
WITH COCKTAILS THAT CATCH FIRE.
YOU KNOW NO BOUNDARY,
DO YOU?
NO.
NO, YOU'RE A MELTING POT
OF MELTING POTS.
CORRECT.
EVERY WALK OF LIFE COMES HERE.
I THINK THERE'S A PARTY
GOIN' ON THE WHOLE TIME.
PRETTY MUCH.
AND WHAT'S A PARTY
WITHOUT PIZZA?
SUZI SUPREME.
HOT ACROSS.
PROBABLY MY FAVORITE PLACE
TO ORDER PIZZA.
DON'T MAKE FUN OF MY
DOUGH-THROWING SKILLS.
ALL KINDS OF COMBINATIONS
DONE LESLIE'S WAY,
LIKE THE PARADISE CITY.
WITH RUM-SOAKED RAISINS?
WE MAKE 'EM.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY SOAKED
IN SOME PINEAPPLE SCHNAPPS
AND COCONUT RUM.
MMM, THOSE ARE TASTY.
THEY'LL BE COMBINED WITH
LESLIE'S HOMEMADE RED SAUCE,
CANADIAN BACON AND ONIONS.
(Leslie) SOME PINEAPPLE
AND SOME RUM RAISINS.
THEN WE PUT THE CHEESE ON
AND THEN WE GOT SOME ROMANO.
MMM, LIKE THE SHARPNESS
OF THAT.
AND SOME OREGANO.
PERFECT.
OH-HO-HO!
MMM. RAISINS.
GREAT CRUST.
THAT'S GOOD PIE.
THANKS.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD PIE.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT
PIZZAS DO YOU HAVE?
13.
ISN'T THAT
AN UNLUCKY NUMBER?
YES.
BUT NOT IF YOU'RE HUNGRY.
CHECK OUT
THE WHITE WINE GARLIC SAUCE
TOPPED WITH ARTICHOKES
AND TOMATOES.
THAT GARLIC SAUCE
AND THAT THIN CRUST--
THAT'S GREAT.
(Leslie) THANKS, GUY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND SHE'S DOIN'
A SUN-DRIED TOMATO
AND GOAT CHEESE DEEP-DISH.
IN THE LAST TEN YEARS,
THAT'S PROBABLY THE BEST
DEEP-DISH I'VE HAD.
IS THERE ANYTHING
RIGHT HERE?
AND CHECK OUT
THE GRILLED CHICKEN PIZZA
WITH A SPICY HOMEMADE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
THAT'S GOT A LITTLE KICK.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
ON THAT ONE.
YEAH.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
I LOVE THAT IT'S
VERY ECLECTIC.
AND YOU CAN COME AND GET PIZZA
OR TATER TOTS.
OR CHEESE CURD,
OR DEEP-FRIED CANDY BARS,
OR A DRINK THAT'S ON FIRE.
THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE THIS
IN THE CITIES.
THIS IS WHERE
I'M HANGIN' OUT.
WHEN I COME BACK TO
MINNEAPOLIS, I'M COMIN' HERE.
WELL, HE LOOKS LIKE HE WORKS
HERE. YOU'VE GOT THE TATTOOS.
I DON'T THINK THE HAIR
FITS HERE THOUGH.
WHAT IS IT, A MOTOR LOUNGE?
NO, YOUR HAIR'S FINE.
"YEAH, HE LOOKS
LIKE HE'S GOT ISSUES.
HE PROBABLY WORKS HERE."
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OH, I LIKE THAT.
KEEP PUTTIN' 'EM ON.
I'LL GIVE YOU ANOTHER ONE.
I GET ANOTHER ONE?
ALL RIGHT, TAKE 'EM BACK OFF
AND PUT 'EM BACK ON AGAIN.
(laughter)