HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--ROUTE 66...
THIS IS MAIN STREET
AMERICA RIGHT HERE.
CLASSIC JOINTS ON
A CLASSIC AMERICAN HIGHWAY...
WHEN PEOPLE COME IN HERE,
THEY'RE STEPPIN' BACK INTO TIME.
THE TRUCKER'S PARADISE
IN THE CALIFORNIA DESERT...
A LITTLE BIT
OF HISTORY TO IT.
WHERE THEY'RE STILL USING
MOM'S BISCUIT RECIPE
FROM 50 YEARS AGO...
WE LOVE IT HERE.
EVERYBODY KNOWS YOUR NAME.
THE OKLAHOMA CAFé
WITH A MENU FROM EVERYWHERE...
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
SPAETZLE--GERMAN FRIED NOODLE.
TOSS IN SOME BEIGNETS.
WOW.
YOU'LL SAY THAT'S THE BEST
ALLIGATOR YOU EVER HAD.
AND OUT-OF-BOUNDS COOKIN'
IN WHAT USED TO BE
A KANSAS BANK...
BACK IN THE HEYDAY.
WHEN ROUTE 66
WAS THE HIGHWAY.
WHERE, THESE DAYS,
THE FOOD IS MONEY.
IT'S KIND OF ECLECTIC
FOR A SMALL TOWN IN KANSAS.
THAT IS OUTSTANDING.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE ON THE CALIFORNIA SIDE
OF ROUTE 66
JUST OUTSIDE OF
VICTORVILLE, CALIFORNIA.
IT IS SO HOT, THERE ARE TONS
OF TRUCKS, AND I AM HUNGRY.
SO NOW IT'S TIME TO PLAY
THE "WHERE AM I GONNA
STOP AND EAT?" GAME.
SO WITH MY KEEN SENSE
OF AWARENESS,
I'M GONNA STOP AND EAT
WHERE THE TRUCKERS EAT--
EMMA JEAN'S HOLLAND BURGER CAFé.
FOLKS AROUND HERE SAY
IT'S A TRUCKER'S PARADISE.
SEE THESE PICTURES ON THE WALLS
OF THESE GRAVEL TRUCKS,
AND THAT'S WHAT WE DO EVERY DAY,
EXCEPT THIS IS 1953,
AND TODAY'S, YOU KNOW, 2007,
BUT THAT'S US RIGHT THERE TODAY.
AFTER 60 YEARS ON THIS STRETCH
OF ROUTE 66,
EMMA JEAN'S IS
JUST LIKE IT WAS.
A LITTLE BIT
OF HISTORY TO IT.
I GOT IT!
IT'S STILL THE MUST STOP...
(horn honks)
THEY KNEW YOU.
THAT'S DAVE.
FOR GREAT HOME COOKIN'.
PICK IT UP.
HERE YOU GO, BOB.
IT'S JUST NOT LIKE THOSE DRIVE-
THROUGH BURGERS, YOU KNOW?
BEST BACON IN TOWN HERE.
BEST BACON?
BEST BACON.
WHERE IS TOWN?
AND FOR BRIAN GENTRY
AND HIS WIFE SHAWNA,
KEEPIN' EVERYTHING THE WAY
IT WAS IS THE WAY IT IS.
WE BOUGHT THE PLACE
WHEN I WAS 13.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
THE HOLLAND BURGER.
THE HOLLAND BURGER SINCE '47.
YEAH.
AND YOU JUST KINDA
TAGLINE IT NOW THE--
EMMA JEAN'S HOLLAND BURGER.
YEAH, WHEN MY MOM HAD IT,
SHE PUT THAT ON THERE.
SO YOUR MOM WAS EMMA JEAN.
YEAH.
I WANT IT TO STAY
AS ORIGINAL AS POSSIBLE,
'CAUSE WHEN PEOPLE
COME IN HERE, THEY--
YOU KNOW, THEY'RE
STEPPIN' BACK INTO TIME.
...BACK BEFORE CHAIN
RESTAURANTS RULED THE ROAD
AND FOLKS STARTED PAYING
WITH PLASTIC,
BACK WHEN FUELING UP MEANT
REAL-DEAL COMFORT FOOD...
BIG JUICY BOMB.
LIKE THE SIGNATURE BISCUITS
AND SAUSAGE GRAVY.
ALWAYS GOOD.
SO WHO TAUGHT YOU HOW
TO MAKE BISCUITS AND GRAVY?
MY MOM.
OKAY, SO A BUNCH OF FLOUR.
I PUT SOME BAKING POWDER
IN THERE, TOO.
WHA--WHA--WHA--
WHAT IS THAT
MEASURING SPOON?
WHAT IS THAT?
LET ME SEE THIS.
WHOSE GRAVY BOAT DID
YOU SNAG THAT OUT OF?
MOM BROUGHT IT HOME
IN HER PURSE.
AT THE DELI.
MY MOM TAUGHT ME HOW TO MAKE
BISCUITS HERE AND PIE DOUGH.
AT THIS TABLE.
AT THIS TABLE RIGHT HERE.
WOW.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME MILK.
OKAY, THAT LOOKS
PRETTY GOOD.
THAT'S THE CONSISTENCY
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
THAT'S IT.
YOU HAVE MIXED THEM ABOUT
AS LITTLE AS POSSIBLE.
YOU GOTTA BE NICE
TO YOUR BISCUITS.
HERE, YOU WANT ME
TO SHOW YOU?
OH, BOY. WHY DO--
YOU GOTTA GET
A GOOD TWIST ON IT.
LOOK AT HIM GO, FOLKS.
HE'S GOT IT NOW.
HE'S GOIN' ALL THE WAY
TO MANAGEMENT.
THEN WE GET THE TRAYS.
WHILE THE BISCUITS BAKE UP,
BRIAN BROWNS THE SAUSAGE
FOR THE GRAVY.
MOM'S RECIPE, ALSO?
MOM'S RECIPE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE SALT IN HERE
AND SOME PEPPER.
NOW WHAT?
WE ADD THE MILK.
WHOA!
WHOO! HOT STUFF.
GIVE IT A WHISK OR TWO.
THAT'S THICK, BRO.
IT IS THICK.
IF IT STANDS UP, IT'S READY.
MMM. THAT'S A REAL-DEAL
BISCUIT RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S TASTY.
I DON'T THINK I COULD EAT
MORE THAN 6 OR 12 OF THESE.
AND BRIAN KNOWS IT'S
THE STICK-TO-YOUR-RIBS STUFF
THAT HIS CROWD'S LOOKIN' FOR.
A LITTLE CHEESE ON THERE.
OKAY.
SO HE'S SCRATCH-COOKIN'
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
HOT BEEF
WITH MASHED POTATOES.
HOW MUCH OF THAT
CAN YOU ACTUALLY EAT?
UM, ON A DAY I DIDN'T
EAT BREAKFAST, ALL OF IT.
I DON'T THINK
THERE'S A RULE BOOK
THAT SAYS YOU HAVE TO MAKE
EVERYTHING. I MEAN, I LIKE IT.
FRESH. DELICIOUS.
YOUR ORDER'S READY, SIR.
THIS IS, LIKE, THE ONE CONSTANT
ON THE WHOLE STRIP.
AND CHECK OUT THE BURGERS.
BIG OLD CHEESEBURGER.
YOU'VE GOTTA LIKE
A HALF POUNDER.
YOU MUST BE PUTTIN' FAST FOOD
CHAINS OUT OF BUSINESS
50 MILES THAT WAY
AND 50 MILES THAT WAY.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S JUST
A BIG ALL-AMERICAN--
ALL-AMERICAN BURGER.
KEEP IT SIMPLE.
IT'S PROBABLY THE BEST
BURGER I'VE EVER HAD.
THERE'S THE BRIAN BURGER...
THIS IS NAMED AFTER ME.
WITH A MILDLY SPICY GREEN CHILI
ON PARMESAN TOAST.
ORTEGA CHILI.
A LITTLE SWISS AMERICAN.
A HALF POUND OF BEEF.
(laughs)
WITH THAT CHEESE
AND ORTEGA CHILI TOGETHER...
SEE, MINE IS THE CRUNCHY
PARMESAN GARLIC ON THE TOP.
I WAS GETTIN' TO THAT.
OH, YOU--I'M SORRY.
I JUMPED RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF YOUR DISCUSSION.
YEAH.
AND THERE'S SOMETHING
CALLED THE TRUCKER SANDWICH.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
TALK ABOUT HOMEMADE.
THIS IS THE TRI-TIP
THAT WE USE FOR...
THE TRUCKER SANDWICH.
FOR THE TRUCKER SANDWICH.
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
WELL, WE PUT IT IN HERE
IN THE PAN.
THEN WE JUST CHOP UP--
CARROTS AND CELERY. SALT.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SPRINKLE.
A LITTLE PEPPER.
A LITTLE SEASON-ALL, AND...
LOVE THAT MEASUREMENT
STYLE, BOSS.
WE GOTTA GET SOME OREGANO.
WE LIKE TO JUST PUT A LITTLE BIT
IN THERE FOR COLOR AND FLAVOR.
WE NEED A LITTLE WATER,
SO WE POUR THAT IN
ALONG THE SIDE HERE.
SO YOU DON'T RUN ALL THAT
SEASONING OFF THE TOP.
YEAH.
NOW WE'LL LET IT COOL
AND THEN SLICE IT?
YEAH.
HE'LL STACK IT WITH CHEESE,
BACON AND ORTEGA CHILI.
NOW HOW WILL WE GET EVER--
EVERYTHING GONNA MELT UP HERE?
WELL, WE PUT A LID ON IT
TO WARM IT ALL UP.
THAT'LL DO IT?
THAT'LL DO IT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THIS OUGHT
TO BE ALL MELTED TOGETHER.
IT FEELS NICE AND WARM.
AND IT GETS A THREE SLICE
WITH A LITTLE...
TOOTHPICK.
A LITTLE DECKER DO.
IS THAT AMERICANA OR WHAT?
WOW.
IS THAT GOOD?
THE THING THAT
SURPRISES ME ABOUT IT
IS THE ORTEGA CHILI.
PRETTY SIMPLE...
BUT PRETTY TASTY.
YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE?
BRIAN SAYS IF I COME BACK
NEXT WEEK OR NEXT YEAR,
IT'LL BE THE SAME.
THIS PLACE IS BUILT
ON HOME COOKIN'
THAT SIMPLY DOESN'T CHANGE.
SO THIS PLACE STAYS THE SAME,
BECAUSE THE PEOPLE HERE
MADE IT STAY THE SAME.
ROUTE 66 IS JUST EXACTLY
WHAT IT IS--ROUTE 66.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN THERE.
FOR 60 YEARS, SO HAS
EMMA JEAN'S HOLLAND BURGER.
KEEP IT THE SAME, YOU KNOW,
KEEP IT SIMPLE, AND--
EVER PAVE THE LOT MAYBE?
PROBABLY NOT.
NO FOIE GRAS.
NO SUSHI.
HAVE YOU EVER
HAD FOIE GRAS?
IT'S THE REAL
DEAL HERE.
NO, I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING EAST
TO OKLAHOMA...
HOLY MOLY,
IT'S THE DINNER DINER BOY.
WHERE THEY'VE GOT SOME BURGERS
THAT NEVER SAID "MOO."
THEY'RE DIFFERENT,
AREN'T THEY?
THEY ARE DIFFERENT.
THIS JOINT'S DIFFERENT.
SO NOW HERE I AM
1,300 MILES EAST OF VICTORVILLE
ON ROUTE 66 IN STROUD, OKLAHOMA.
NOW IT'S STILL HOT,
AND I'M STILL HUNGRY,
BUT THIS TIME,
I DON'T HAVE TO QUESTION
WHERE TO STOP AND EAT.
OF COURSE,
IT'S AT THIS 67-YEAR-OLD JOINT
THAT WAS BUILT FROM THE ROCK
OF ROUTE 66.
THEY WERE BUILDING ROADS,
AND SO THERE WAS A LOT
OF ROCK AVAILABLE.
THERE WAS A MAN
NAMED ROY RIEVES.
HE BUILT THE BUILDING
SINGLE-HANDEDLY, PRETTY MUCH.
HE ONLY HAD ONE HAND?
YEAH, HE ONLY HAD
ONE OF 'EM. (laughs)
JUST A LOT OF HISTORY HERE.
IT'S GREAT FOOD.
RAISE YOUR HAND
IF YOU WANT ONIONS.
ONE COKE. ONE DR. PEPPER.
SEE SOMETHIN' OTHER THAN
THE EVERYDAY FAST FOODS.
ORDER UP!
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN COMIN' HERE?
HOW LONG HAS
SHE BEEN OPEN?
THE JOINT'S BEEN OPEN
SINCE '39.
DAWN WELCH TOOK OVER IN '93.
I COULDN'T COOK
WHEN I FIRST GOT HERE.
DON'T TELL ANYONE THAT.
NO.
BUT SHE'S BEEN
COOKIN' UP A STORM...
MAGIC CHICKEN.
IN A NONSTOP PARTY EVER SINCE.
WHAT IS UP?
VERY LITTLE. HOLY MOLY,
IT'S THE DINNER DINER BOY.
(laughs)
BUT EVEN MORE
THAN THE GOOD TIMES,
IT'S THE GOOD FOOD
THAT DRAWS A CROWD.
"IT'S ALL SPECIAL."
SHE'S GOT SUCH A VARIETY.
I TRY TO DO SOMETHING
DIFFERENT ALL THE TIME.
FROM HOMEMADE
GERMAN JAEGER SCHNITZEL
TO NEW ORLEAN'S-STYLE BEIGNETS,
FROM GRILLED SHRIMP
TO A REUBEN ON MARBLE RYE,
THE MENU GOES ON FOREVER.
CHEESE CURLY FRIES.
THOSE GO RIGHT ALONG
FOR BREAKFAST.
I LIKE THEIR CRêPES.
'CAUSE YOU DON'T FIND CRêPES
AT EVERY BURGER JOINT.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW WE HAVE SOME BARBECUE.
OH, THEN SOME
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
THAT REALLY--THAT'S--
I SEE THE THEME NOW.
EXACTLY--ECLECTIC.
EVEN THE BURGERS
ARE SOMETHIN' ELSE.
(Dawn) HERE'S
YOUR BUFFALO BURGER
WITH PICKLES
AND ONION ONLY.
YOU BETCHA.
BUFFALO BURGER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LIKE... (imitates buffalo)
LIKE HORNS.
I LIKE 'EM, YEAH.
THEY'RE TASTY.
FRESH GROUND BUFFALO.
GOTTA HAVE THE ONIONS.
OH, THE ONIONS
GO RIGHT ON TOP.
JUST SLIDE THAT BABY
RIGHT ON THERE.
♪♪
GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND WHY STOP WITH BUFFALO?
CHECK OUT THE ALLIGATOR BURGER.
I WENT TO LOUISIANA
AND LEARNED HOW TO COOK.
YOU WRANGLED YOURSELF UP
AN ALLIGATOR.
I WRANGLED MYSELF
AN ALLIGATOR HUNTER.
HE PUTS IT IN A MIX
LIKE A SALMON PATTY--
EGGS AND MILK
AND, UM, THE SPICES.
YOU CAN SEE THERE'S
GREEN ONION IN IT.
SO I'M A LITTLE FREAKY DEAKY
RIGHT NOW ON THE, UH...
OH, YOU'LL SAY THAT'S THE BEST
ALLIGATOR YOU EVER HAD.
♪♪
KNOW WHAT IT REMINDS ME OF?
OH, UH, NO. TELL ME.
ALLIGATOR.
(indistinct)
DELICIOUS. YEAH,
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THEY'RE DIFFERENT,
AREN'T THEY?
THEY ARE DIFFERENT.
I MEAN, YOU GOTTA BE--
THIS JOINT'S DIFFERENT.
FOLKS AROUND HERE
LIKE IT THAT WAY.
AARON'S IN THE HOUSE.
(man) SEE YOU.
THEY'VE GOTTEN USED
TO THEIR ALLIGATOR BURGERS...
AND BEIGNETS.
AND THEIR SCRATCH-MADE
BEIGNETS...
(Guy) HAVE YOU HAD
THESE BEFORE?
OH, I HAVE 'EM
ALL THE TIME.
YOU HAVE THEM
ALL THE TIME?
WHEN YOU ORDER 'EM,
WE JUST KINDA MIX IT UP HERE.
THOSE FRENCH KIND OF DONUTS
THAT ARE A SIGNATURE DISH
DOWN IN NEW ORLEANS.
GIVE IT SOME LOVE.
WOW. OH, GAH.
THAT IS A HOT FRIED DONUT.
EVEN SOME GERMAN HOME COOKING.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
SPAETZLE--GERMAN FRIED NOODLE.
IN GERMANY, THEY SERVE IT AS
A SIDE DISH LIKE A FRENCH FRY.
GIVE THAT TO ME.
IT'S A FLOUR,
MILK AND EGG DOUGH.
I JUST TURNED OVER
THE KITCHEN, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THROW IT DOWN IN HERE.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA KINDA--
SO WE'RE GONNA KNEAD IT?
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
OF WORKIN' OVER.
PUSH IT AROUND.
SO THESE ARE LITTLE
GERMAN PASTA NIBBLES.
YEAH.
NOW WE DUNK IT
IN THE WATER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DUNK IT
BOILING WATER.
IT'LL BE SPLASHIN' US.
WE'RE GONNA STIR THIS,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA WAIT
TILL IT COMES BOILIN'
UP TO THE TOP.
YOUR POT IS BOILING OVER.
I'M ASKING YOU
WHAT TO DO WITH IT.
WE ARE DONE
WITH THAT BABY.
WHERE DO YOU
WANT 'EM TO GO?
LET'S GET HER--
LET'S SHUT HER DOWN.
ALL RIGHT, KIND OF
JUST LET THAT SIT THERE
AND COOK A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW YOU'RE GONNA
ADD THE MAGIC SPICE.
MAGIC SPICE?
THE MAGIC SPICE.
THEY LOOK LIKE BACO BITS.
YEAH, SOMETHIN' SIMILAR.
SHE'LL SERVE IT UP
WITH JAEGER SCHNITZEL...
THERE'S YOUR PORK.
KIND OF A GERMAN
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
WHAT IS THIS,
CRACKER CRUMB MEAL?
IT'S GOT FLOUR, CRACKER MEAL
AND SALT AND PEPPER.
RIGHT HERE.
RIGHT THERE?
I HAVE THIS. I WILL USE IT.
BECAUSE IT'S STARTIN'
TO PULL UP A LITTLE BIT...
YEAH.
YOU CAN JUST--SHRUNK IN.
SO FLIP HER?
FLIP HER OVER.
OKAY, SO MAKE THE GRAVY.
WE ADD THE BACON.
HOW OFTEN DO YOU
MAKE THE GRAVY?
ABOUT EVERY DAY.
SOMETIMES TWICE A DAY.
EVERY DAY? REALLY?
YEAH, 'CAUSE WE MAKE IT
IN SMALL BATCHES
TO MAKE IT--KEEP IT
A LITTLE BIT FRESHER.
PUT IT ON TOP OF THIS.
THE BACON,
MUSHROOM, ONION...
JAEGER SCHNITZEL.
HOW--HOW--HOW--HOW--
JEEZ. I CAN'T EVEN SEE IT.
THERE YOU CAN SEE IT.
OH, YEAH.
MMM.
GOOD?
I LIKE THAT.
SAUCE IS GOOD.
I COULD SERIOUSLY
PUT DOWN...
BUCKET LOADS OF THAT.
THIS WHOLE THING.
I--THIS IS GREAT.
I'M A BIG GRAVY PERSON,
SO I ENJOY THE GRAVY
AND THE WAY IT
COMPLEMENTS THE PORK.
I JUST THINK THIS IS
THE MOST ECLECTIC MENU.
I MEAN, ROUTE 66 HAS ALL
THIS MYSTERY BEHIND IT
AND ALL OF THIS LORE,
AND I JUST THINK THAT
COMIN' HERE JUST--
IT'S KIND OF LIKE--
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S OUT OF A MOVIE.
ACTUALLY, IT IS.
DAWN AND HER RESTAURANT
HELPED INSPIRE THE FOLKS
WHO MADE THE MOVIE "CARS."
SO THEY HUNG OUT
IN STROUD?
OH, YEAH. THEY CAME OUT
AND HUNG OUT WITH ME A LOT.
THEY DEVELOPED CHARACTERS
BASED ON REAL LIFE.
I'M SALLY THE PORSCHE 911.
I'M NOT THE VOICE,
BUT I'M HER IN REAL LIFE.
AND IN REAL LIFE, DAWN'S PLACE
IS FILLED WITH CHARACTERS...
(Guy) ANYBODY EVER TELL YOU
THAT YOU LOOK LIKE...
ARE YOU SURE?
THE EASTER BUNNY?
AND WITH CHARACTER...
SO YOU'RE THE ONE THAT DID
ALL OF THESE DECORATIONS?
OH, YEAH, CAN'T YOU TELL?
I MEAN, I PUT A LOT OF EFFORT
INTO MAKIN' 'EM
STRAIGHT AND NEAT.
AND KEEPING THE PLACE
THE LANDMARK IT'S BEEN
SINCE THE BEGINNING OF ROUTE 66
WHILE FILLING IT
WITH HER OWN PERSONALITY,
HER OWN WAY OF DOIN' THINGS
AND HER OWN HOME COOKIN'
OF A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
THIS IS MY BRAINSTORM.
THESE ARE MY BABIES.
STIR FRY CAME UP TO ME
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
WOW.
YOU WON'T FORGET ME.
I'M PRETTY MEMORABLE.
I-I DON'T THINK
I'M GOIN' TO BE ABLE TO.
NEXT, ROUTE 66 TAKES US
TO KANSAS...
HI, FOLKS.
HOW YOU DOIN' TONIGHT?
HI. JUST FINE.
TO A SMALL TOWN WITH BIG FOOD.
THAT'S YIPPEE-YI-YAY YUMMY.
I'M ON THE FINAL LEG
OF MY ROUTE 66 ROAD TRIP
FROM CALI TO KANSAS,
AND THAT'S WHERE I AM NOW--
BAXTER SPRINGS, KANSAS.
NOW CHECK OUT THIS JOINT.
IT USED TO BE A BANK.
IT WAS ACTUALLY HELD UP
BY JESSE JAMES IN 1876.
IT'S CALLED CAFé ON THE ROUTE,
AND THEY'VE GOT SOME FOOD
ON ROUTE 66
THAT YOU MIGHT NOT EXPECT.
WELL, I'M GONNA DO SOMETHING
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
HOW DOES THIS STACK UP?
EXCELLENT.
EXCELLENT?
(man) IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT'S KIND OF ECLECTIC
FOR A SMALL TOWN IN KANSAS.
IT'S WONDERFUL. IT REALLY IS.
YOU'VE GOT YOUR
APPLE-AND-BACON-STUFFED SALMON,
YOUR NUT-CRUSTED CATFISH,
PINEAPPLE GARLIC CHICKEN,
RIB EYE IN A TOMATO
AND WHITE-WINE SAUCE,
AND GET A LOAD
OF THE TWICE-BAKED POTATOES
AND THE DEEP-FRIED
CHEESE CAKE.
WELL, I WAS A CHEF
IN KANSAS CITY
AT SEVERAL
DIFFERENT LOCATIONS--
FINE DINING, AMUSEMENT PARKS,
YOU KNOW, THINGS LIKE THAT.
YOU'VE DONE FROM
FILET MIGNON TO CORN DOG.
(indistinct)
NINE YEARS AGO, CHEF RICHARD
SANELL AND HIS WIFE AMY
DECIDED TO MAKE A CHANGE.
AND YOU SAY, "LET'S GET
OUT OF KANSAS CITY.
LET'S MOVE
TO BAXTER SPRINGS."
IT WAS AN OLD DINER, AND IT
WAS AROUND SINCE THE '40s.
BACK IN THE HEYDAY...
BACK IN THE DAY WHEN--
THIS PLACE WAS...
WHEN ROUTE 66
WAS THE HIGHWAY,
YOU KNOW,
THIS PLACE WAS HOPPIN'.
IT'S HOPPIN' AGAIN.
HI, FOLKS.
HOW YOU DOIN' TONIGHT?
HI. JUST FINE.
THEY'RE PACKIN'
IN THE CROWDS...
CHEESECAKE BUÑUELO HERE.
WITH THE KIND OF
TOTAL SCRATCH COOKIN'
YOU'D NEVER EXPECT
TO FIND HERE.
IT'S THE AZTEC CHICKEN,
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THEN THERE'S
AN EGG-BATTERED CHICKEN
THAT HAS SHRIMP, CHILIES,
AVOCADOS, BACON
AND A RUM GLAZE.
SO NOW WE GO DOWN
WITH THE SHRIMP?
WE'RE GONNA GO DOWN
WITH THE SHRIMP,
AND WE'RE--
SO THOSE ARE GONNA PICK UP
SOME OF THE FLAVOR.
RIGHT, AND NOW WE'RE
GONNA GO AHEAD--
BECAUSE IT'S COOKING FAST,
WE'RE GONNA ADD JUST PROBABLY
RIGHT ADD A TEASPOON
OF GARLIC.
I LIKE YOUR TEASPOON, BUDDY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF CHOPPED BACON,
'CAUSE WE'RE GONNA
PICK UP THE FAT.
'CAUSE THAT NEVER HURTS.
PUT IN THE CHILIES.
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH THE RUM,
A 2-SECOND POUR.
THERE WE GO.
THEN WE'LL ADD JUST A LITTLE
BIT OF CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY. NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE AVOCADOS.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. MAN.
THAT IS OUTSTANDING.
DUDE.
COOL.
GET IT TO WIN IT
ON ROUTE 66.
AND WHY NOT?
RICHARD'S OUT TO PROVE YOU
DON'T NEED TO BE IN A BIG CITY
TO FIND FOLKS WHO APPRECIATE
BIG-TIME COOKIN'...
AN EXCELLENT, EXCELLENT MEAL.
LIKE HIS SMOKED,
STUFFED SALMON.
STUFFED WITH APPLES,
BACON, HONEY AND CHIVES
AND THEN--AND THEN
IT'S EUROPEAN SMOKE,
WHICH MEANS IT'S SMOKED
ON THE STOVE TOP.
ALLOWS THE FLAVOR OF THE SALMON
AND THE CURE TO COME THROUGH.
WE'RE GONNA JUST CUT A POCKET
RIGHT IN THE CENTER
SO THAT YOU CAN PUT YOUR
APPLES IN DEEP ENOUGH.
THEN WE LIFT OPEN.
OH, HAPPY SALMON.
THEN WHAT WE DO IS--
AND THIS IS KIND OF
THE APPARATUS THAT WE HAVE--
IT'S JUST A PAN
WITH A SCREEN,
AND THIS IS SMOKE--
THIS IS OUR SMOKING DUST.
IT IS HICKORY, OAK
AND A LITTLE CHERRYWOOD.
YOU SET IT IN
JUST LIKE THAT.
WE'LL COOK THAT FOR ABOUT
FIVE, MAYBE SIX MINUTES,
AND WE'LL FINISH IT
IN THE OVEN.
WE GRAB ABOUT SIX,
EIGHT MANDARIN ORANGES.
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
JUST WITH A LITTLE RUM.
FLAME IT AND TAKE
A LITTLE SOFTENED BUTTER...
AND JUST MAKIN' A NICE
LITTLE TIGHT PAN SAUCE...
EXACTLY.
THAT'S GONNA GO
OVER THE TOP OF IT.
EXACTLY.
SERVE THAT ON MY HAND,
IT'D BE GOOD.
RIGHT OVER THE TOP
LIKE THIS?
RIGHT OVER THE TOP.
TALK ABOUT AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVORS, DUDE.
OKAY.
BUT NICE LIGHT SMOKE.
STILL TASTE THE SALMON.
A LITTLE NUGGET
OF BACON IN THERE.
NOT A DISH THAT
I WOULD EXPECT TO FIND
ON ROUTE 66.
I HOPE NOT.
THEN THAT DOESN'T
MAKE US SPECIAL.
YUH-HUH. DON'T WORRY,
RICHARD, YOU'RE SPECIAL.
EVEN THE BASICS HERE
AREN'T SO BASIC.
I HAD THE CHICKEN SALAD.
IT HAS A LITTLE BIT OF GRAPES.
IT HAS SOME WALNUTS,
AND IT'S EXCELLENT.
TURKEY, HAM
AND CHEESE SANDWICH.
BUT ON A PITA.
ON PITA.
AND THIS AIN'T GRANDMA'S
OLD POTATO SALAD.
THAT IS THE BEST
IN THE WORLD.
IT IS THE BEST?
THE BEST.
YOU KNOW, IT'S A CRUNCHY TASTE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
HE'S DEEP-FRYIN' IT.
WHAT WE REALLY GO FOR IS
JUST A NICE GOLDEN BROWN
SO YOU GET THE CRUNCHINESS
ON THE OUTSIDE
AND THAT SOFT POTATO
ON THE INSIDE.
MMM.
I WISH YOU'D MADE SOME
FOR YOURSELF.
(laughs)
WELL, I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO GET A FORK IN THERE.
WELL...
YEAH, WE'LL SEE.
TWO PARTS MAYONNAISE
TO ONE PART MUSTARD,
AND THEN ALL WE DO IS ADD
A LITTLE SEASONING SALT TO IT
BEFORE WE ADD
THE POTATOES.
NOW WHAT KIND OF
SEASONED SALT IS THAT?
WELL, THAT'S A SPECIAL
SEASONING SALT THAT I USE,
UH, THAT I REALLY
CAN'T DIVULGE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME?
NO, I WON'T TELL YA.
OH, I THOUGHT
WE WERE BUDDIES.
DROP IT IN.
LOOK AT THAT!
THERE'S A SPOON FOR YOU.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S TASTY.
AND THE THING IS IS YOU DON'T
HAVE ANY UNIFORM CUTS HERE.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO THERE'S SOME IN HERE
THAT'S REAL CRUNCHY.
SOME THAT ARE REAL SOFT.
THAT'S YIPPEE-YI-YAY YUMMY.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
HOW LONG DO WE FRY IT FOR?
RICHARD CAN'T STOP CRYING.
GOLDEN BROWN.
AND YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT
THIS THING'S STUFFED WITH.
YOU'RE KNOCKIN' THE BALL
OUT OF THE PARK.
HERE AT CAFé ON THE ROUTE
IN BAXTER SPRINGS, KANSAS,
CHEF RICHARD SANELL
IS REWRITING THE RULES
ON SMALL-TOWN COOKING...
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
EXACTLY LIKE IT.
AND THAT INCLUDES DESSERT.
AND IT HAS THE CHEESECAKE
FILLING IN THE MIDDLE.
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
WE CALL IT
A BUÑUELO CHEESECAKE.
A BUÑUELO IS JUST A FLOUR
TORTILLA THAT IS DEEP FRIED,
AND IT'S USUALLY TOPPED
WITH CINNAMON SUGAR.
UH-HUH.
AND THEN MOST PEOPLE
WHO EAT IT
PUT ICE CREAM AND STRAWBERRY
SAUCE AND ALL THAT ON THERE.
THAT'S A BUÑUELO.
THIS IS REGULAR
CREAM CHEESE.
WE PUT A POUND OF POWDERED
SUGAR--EQUAL PARTS.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE
IT'S SWEET ENOUGH.
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO CALL JESSE JAMES
AND LET HIM KNOW HE LEFT
HIS MIXER HERE, TOO.
WE TAKE A 10-INCH
FLOUR TORTILLA.
WE HIT IT STRAIGHT
ACROSS LIKE THAT.
SO, I MEAN, THIS IS
ALMOST GETTIN' INTO,
LIKE, MEXICAN
CANNOLI RIGHT NOW.
IT COULD BE
CONSIDERED THAT.
WE'RE GONNA EGG-WASH
THE CORNERS,
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA ROLL IT UP,
AND THEN WE DROP THAT
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
WE FRY IT TILL
IT'S GOLDEN BROWN,
USUALLY ABOUT TWO,
MAYBE THREE MINUTES.
TAKE IT OVER
TO CINNAMON SUGAR.
AND THEN WE HIT THAT,
AND THAT HELPS TO KINDA ABSORB
WHATEVER EXCESS OIL
MIGHT BE ON THERE.
OH, OKAY.
AND THIS IS A LITTLE
STRAWBERRY SAUCE
WITH SOME FRESH
STRAWBERRIES?
EXACTLY.
DUMP HER ON?
GO FOR IT.
THAT'S A DESSERT FOR NINE.
THE CRUST IS
LIGHT AND FLAKY.
OH, I'M DONE.
THIS RIGHT HERE
WITH THE CREAM CHEESE...
A LITTLE BIT
OF CINNAMON IN THERE.
YOU'RE KNOCKIN' THE BALL
OUT OF THE PARK.
JUST ASK THE FANS.
ONE OF THE NUMBER ONE
RESTAURANTS IN THE AREA?
YES.
THE NUMBER ONE.
THE NUMBER ONE RESTAURANT
IN THE AREA.
THE NUMBER ONE.
WOW. YOU GO, GIRL.
AND AFTER MORE THAN 100 YEARS,
THIS PLACE ISN'T
THE OLD BANK ANYMORE...
YOU GUYS WANT TWO TABLES?
OR EVEN THE OLD DINER
FOLKS REMEMBER.
IT'S RICHARD AND AMY'S PLACE...
THIS IS MAIN STREET
AMERICA RIGHT HERE.
IN THE HEART
OF A SMALL KANSAS TOWN.
WHEN WE COME IN HERE,
WE NEVER FAIL TO SEE
SOMEONE THAT WE KNOW.
AND ONCE YOU'RE HERE,
YOU'RE PART OF THE FAMILY.
ALL RIGHT,
I'M YOUR AUNT D.J. NOW.
MY AUNT D.J... FITS.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
HEY...
(mumbling with mouth full)
EH?
I DON'T SAY
THAT TO EVERYBODY.
WELL, THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE THAT.