HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(Guy) WHOA!
SOME GREAT JOINTS
THAT ARE ONE OF A KIND...
THAT MIGHT BE ILLEGAL
TO SERVE.
THE MASSACHUSETTS
SEAFOOD SHACK...
IT'S WONDERFUL.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOIN' CLAMS
THEIR WAY FOR 70 YEARS.
THE BEST CLAMS IN ESSEX--
THE HOME OF THE FRIED CLAMS.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT YOU COULD
ORDER CLAMS WITH BELLIES
OR WITHOUT BELLIES.
THE MICHIGAN JOINT WHERE
THE NAME SAYS IT ALL...
(man) ALL RIGHT,
GIZZARDS UP!
HALF A DOZEN GIZZARDS.
JOE'S GIZZARD CITY.
THESE GIZZARDS
ARE THE BEST.
IF YOU SAY IT TASTES
LIKE CHICKEN, I'M LEAVIN'.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO SAN FRANCISCO
FOR DINER FOOD
LIKE MOM USED TO MAKE...
(Guy) OH-HO,
LOOK AT THAT!
IF YOUR MOM GREW UP
IN PORTUGAL.
THAT IS FANTASTIC!
AND REAL-DEAL MEXICAN FOOD
BY THE SIDE OF THE HIGHWAY.
THAT'S KILLER.
I WOULD EAT HERE
EVERY DAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHAT KIND OF WEATHER
YOU'RE GONNA GET HERE
IN NEW ENGLAND.
SO HERE I AM IN ESSEX,
MASSACHUSETTS.
REGARDLESS OF THE RAIN
OR THE ELEMENTS,
I GOTTA CHECK OUT THIS JOINT--
J.T. FARNHAM'S.
FOLKS AROUND HERE SAY
THEY HAVE GOT
SOME OF THE BEST FRIED
WHOLE-BELLY CLAMS, AND ME?
WELL, I'M ALWAYS LOOKIN'
TO MACK ON A LOBSTER ROLL.
IN IT TO WIN IT
ON THAT, MAN.
AND ON EVERYTHING ELSE ON
THE MENU, LIKE FRESH SCALLOPS,
GRILLED HADDOCK,
ALL KINDS OF FRIED SEAFOOD...
THIS HAS BEEN PERFECT HERE.
AND ESPECIALLY THE FRIED CLAMS,
WHICH FOLKS HAVE BEEN
COMIN' HERE TO GET...
YUMMY!
FOR 70 YEARS.
(woman) VERY GOOD. I'M EATING
THE FAMOUS FRIED CLAMS.
PERFECT.
SHE'S HAVING A CLAM ROLL.
SHE'S HAVING
THE SMALL CLAMS.
(bell dings)
AND THE FAVORITES HERE
ARE THE REAL DEAL--
NOT CLAM STRIPS,
BUT THE WHOLE-BELLY CLAMS
WITH A BIG, SOFT CENTER.
YOU HAVE TO BE BRAVE
AND TRY ONE.
NUMBER 15, YOUR ORDER'S READY
AT THE TAKEOUT WINDOW.
I THINK THERE'S A LOT MORE
FLAVOR IN THE WHOLE BELLY.
THERE'S ONLY
ONE FRIED CLAM.
(Guy) THERE'S ONLY
ONE FRIED CLAM?
HAS BELLIES.
HAS BELLIES?
CLAM STRIPS ARE NOT
CLAMS IN MY--
THAT'S FOR CHEATERS.
RIGHT.
THOSE ARE FOR, UH,
CITY DWELLERS.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT YOU COULD
ORDER CLAMS WITH BELLIES
OR WITHOUT BELLIES.
WE DON'T--WE DON'T--
(woman) WHERE ARE
YOU FROM?
MARS.
WHOLE-BELLIES OR STRIPS?
HA-HA, 'CAUSE I KNOW--
(woman) WHOLE BELLIES.
WHOLE-BELLIES?
WHOLE-BELLIES.
THE WHOLE-BELLIES HAVE BEEN
THE LOCAL FLAVOR FOREVER
FOR FOLKS GROWIN' UP
AROUND HERE,
LIKE JOE AND TERRY CELLUCCI,
WHO JUMPED AT THE CHANCE
TO BUY THIS LOCAL LANDMARK
14 YEARS AGO.
(Guy) AND YOU WEREN'T
RESTAURANT PEOPLE THOUGH.
NO.
(Terry) I WAS
A STAY-AT-HOME MOM.
AND WOULD YOU LIKE SOME
TARTAR SAUCE OR KETCHUP?
(Joe) I WAS PUSHIN' COMPUTERS.
I WAS IN THE HIGH-TECH FIELD.
I MEAN, ARE YOU CRAZY?
UH, YEAH, I THINK SO.
NUMBER 42?
BUT MORE, THEY'RE LOCALS...
SCALLOP BOAT
WITH ONION RINGS.
WHO COULDN'T
RESIST THE CHANCE
TO RETURN THIS PLACE
TO ITS HEYDAY...
AND DID YOU NEED
SOME TARTAR SAUCE?
ONE CLAM AT A TIME.
(Guy) WHAT IS THIS
BATTERING MIXTURE?
(Joe) THERE'S NO MIXTURE IN IT.
IT'S JUST CORN FLOUR.
CORN FLOUR? NO SALT?
NO PEPPER? NO GARLIC POWDER?
NO--
NOTHING.
WE'RE OUT JUST TO GET
THE SEAFOOD FLAVOR.
AND WHAT DOES IT GO IN
TO GET WET?
UH, THAT'S
JUST EVAPORATED MILK.
AND WHAT'S THIS?
WE'RE NOT DIVULGING
THAT PORTION OF IT.
THIS IS SECRET WASH
INFORMATION?
YES.
POUR THIS IN?
OR WHAT DO WE DO?
YES, THAT'S IT.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THAT
ALL TOGETHER.
JUST MAKE SURE WE GET A NICE
LITTLE WHIP OUT OF IT.
EVERYTHING GOES
IN THERE NOW.
IPSWITCH NATIVE
CLAMS TODAY.
I'M JUST MAKIN' SURE
EVERYTHING'S COVERED
SO THE COATING, WHEN IT'S
COOKED, WILL BE UNIFORM.
AND ONCE THE EXTRA FLOUR
IS KNOCKED OFF...
JOE SAYS THE SECRET
TO FRYIN' 'EM RIGHT
IS CHANGING THE OIL
AS OFTEN AS EVERY TWO HOURS
TO KEEP THE CLAM TASTE
CLEAN AND PURE.
(woman) YOU GET
A GOOD CLAM TASTE,
AND IT'S--BUT IT'S NEVER
AN OLD CLAM TASTE.
YOU TASTE THE SEAFOOD MORE THAN
YOU TASTE THE FRIED.
OH, IT'S WONDERFUL.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(man) THESE ARE THE BEST
CLAMS IN ESSEX,
THE HOME
OF THE FRIED CLAMS.
(woman) WE'RE FROM
TAMPA, FLORIDA.
(Guy) WHAT ARE YOU
DOIN' UP HERE?
EATIN' CLAMS!
WE CAME THE WHOLE WAY TO GET
AN ORDER OF FRIED CLAMS.
BUT AS BIG AS THE CLAMS
ARE HERE...
THE WHOLE THING.
FOR LOTS OF FOLKS, THEY'RE
JUST PART OF THE MAIN EVENT.
THE NUMBER ONE-SELLING ITEM
ON THE MENU?
IS THE FISHERMAN'S
COMBO.
FISHERMAN'S COMBO--HOW'D YOU
COME UP WITH THE NAME?
IT'S GOT IT ALL--
FISH, SCALLOPS,
SHRIMP, CLAMS, RINGS
AND FRIES.
THAT'S A BIG PLATE OF FRIED.
YOU SHOULD FRY THE PLATE, TOO.
NOW YOU CAN TOSS
IT ALL TOGETHER?
OR YOU DO IT INDIVIDUALLY?
I ACTUALLY COOK 'EM
IN TWO GROUPS.
'KAY.
THE SCALLOPS AND FISH
CAN GO IN ONE FRYER.
ONCE I DREDGE EVERYTHING,
I'M JUST MAKIN' SURE
EVERYTHING'S COVERED,
SO THE COATING
WHEN IT'S COOKED
WILL BE UNIFORM.
WE'LL LAY THE FISH
DOWN FLAT.
SCALLOPS WITHOUT
COVERING THE FISH,
'CAUSE THAT'LL EFFECT
THE COATING,
SO WE HAVE TO KIND OF
SEPARATE THOSE TWO.
SHRIMP AND CLAMS--TAKE AS MUCH
OF THE EXTRA LOOSE STUFF
OUTTA THERE, SO I'M NOT
THROWING A BUNCH OF CORN FLOUR
IN THE MIX.
THE SCALLOPS AND
THE FLOUNDER TAKE LONGER.
MAYBE THREE OR FOUR
MINUTES TO COOK.
THE RINGS MIGHT TAKE TWO
TO THREE MINUTES TO COOK.
I LIKE THAT COLOR. IT'S JUST
BEYOND THE CANARY YELLOW
INTO A BROWNISH STAGE.
IF YOU'VE DONE YOUR
TIMING EXACTLY RIGHT?
IT ALL COMES OUT AT ONCE.
THAT'S A HANDFUL.
FISH LOOKS NICE AND LIGHT
AND FLAKY.
IT'S TASTY FISH.
THESE SHRIMP ARE MINE.
AND THEN THE SCALLOPS--
DAY SCALLOPS?
YES.
'CAUSE THEY CAUGHT
'EM THAT DAY?
MMM, SCALLOPS
ARE NICE AND TENDER.
YEAH.
SCALLOPS THAT ARE JUST, YOU
KNOW, THEY'RE SO FRESH HERE.
EVERYTHING IS.
PART OF MY JOB IS--
IS TO TALK
TO THE SEAFOOD GUYS DAILY--
"WHAT DO YOU GOT?
WHAT'S GOOD?"
SOME DAYS I MIGHT NOT ORDER.
SOME DAYS I ORDER HEAVY.
BUT WHATEVER HE'S GOT
THAT DAY...
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
JOE'S RULE IS--
LET THE SEAFOOD DO THE TALKING
AS MANY WAYS AS IT CAN.
CLAM CHOWDER--
AND THIS IS GREAT CHOWDER?
I THINK SO.
(Terry) WE DO A CLAM CHOWDER,
A HADDOCK CHOWDER,
AND A MANHATTAN SCALLOP CHOWDER.
(man) THE SEA--CLAMS--
IT'S WONDERFUL.
IT'S WHAT CHOWDER IS
SUPPOSED TO BE ABOUT.
AND FRESH LOBSTER...
(Guy) WHOA!
STEAMED, FRIED OR GRILLED.
FRIES, RINGS AND SLAW.
THAT GUY'S READY TO GO.
DON'T EVEN INTERRUPT ME.
WE HAVE SOME FRESH
LOBSTER MEAT.
(grunts)
IS THAT WORKING?
DON'T TALK
DURING THIS ONE.
OKAY.
I'M HAVING KNUCKLE
RIGHT NOW.
OH, I DO ENJOY
THE KNUCKLE.
GIVE 'EM SOME SPACE.
THAT IS THE BEST.
YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE FOLKS SAY
IS THE BEST--
THE WHOLE VIBE OF THE JOINT.
IT REALLY IS ONE OF A KIND.
CLAM PLATE AND
A GRILLED HADDOCK SANDWICH.
AND IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT'S EXACTLY
WHAT YOU HOPE TO FIND
WHEN YOU SEE A LOCAL PLACE
LIKE THIS.
THEY KEEP IT SIMPLE HERE,
AND SOMETIMES SIMPLE IS BEST.
THE FOOD...
THE FOOD HERE
IS AMAZINGLY FRESH.
THE FEEL...
I LIKE THE ATMOSPHERE.
I LIKE IT THE, UH, THE BEST
AS FAR AS JUST BEING
MORE OF A LOCAL FEEL.
AND THE FOLKS RUNNING
THE JOINT,
COMMITTED TO KEEPING
TRADITION ALIVE.
THIS IS LIKE A FOND MEMORY
COMING HERE NOW,
BECAUSE THE KIDS
ARE ALL GROWN AND GONE.
WE'LL BE BRINGING
THE GRAND CHILDREN HERE.
(Guy) YOU HAPPY THAT YOU
MADE THE MOVE IN '94?
YES, OH, YES, IT'S BEEN
VERY GOOD FOR US.
LIFE CHANGING.
(Terry) IT'S THE BEST THING
WE EVER DID, YEAH.
BESIDES MARRYING
EACH OTHER.
UP NEXT...
IF YOU SAY IT TASTES
LIKE CHICKEN, I'M LEAVIN'.
NO.
ONE OF A KIND IN MICHIGAN.
(man) GIZZARD'S UP!
WE'RE GOIN' FOR THE GIZZARDS.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE YOU'RE
GONNA WANT TO TRY 'EM.
EVERYWHERE ELSE
IS GONNA TASTE LIKE YOU BIT
INTO YOUR TENNIS SHOE.
WHEN YOU'RE EATIN'
FRIED CHICKEN,
YOU USUALLY GET ASKED,
"YOU WANT THE BREAST?"
"YOU WANT THE THIGH?"
OR "YOU WANT THE DRUMSTICK?"
WELL, UNLESS YOU'RE
IN POTTERVILLE, MICHIGAN,
WHERE THEY ASK, "HEY, HOW YOU
WANT YOUR GIZZARDS?"
WELCOME TO JOE'S GIZZARD CITY,
TRULY ONE OF A KIND.
(man) ALL RIGHT,
GIZZARDS UP!
HALF A DOZEN GIZZARDS.
IF YOU SAY IT TASTES LIKE
CHICKEN, I'M LEAVIN'.
NO.
YOU'VE ALREADY HAD A DOZEN.
(man) THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
YOU'RE GONNA WANT TO TRY 'EM.
EVERYWHERE ELSE
IS GONNA TASTE LIKE YOU BIT
INTO YOUR TENNIS SHOE
OR YOUR BELT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN
MY BELT IN YEARS.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE
ON THE MENU--
THE BURGER.
CAN'T GET A BETTER
CHEESEBURGER THAN JOE'S.
THE MASSIVE FISH AND FRIES.
(Guy) LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT.
EVEN DEEP-FRIED DESSERTS.
IT'S KIND OF AN OFF-THE-WALL,
UNUSUAL PLACE TO GO.
BUT WITH A NAME LIKE
JOE'S GIZZARD CITY,
YOU KNOW WHY I'M HERE.
GIZZARD'S UP!
AND THEY'RE THE BEST
GIZZARDS IN THE WORLD.
(Guy) WHO ELSE
HAS GIZZARD?
ALLIGATORS AND EARTHWORMS.
THANK GOODNESS WE'RE SERVIN'
'EM FROM CHICKENS.
THAT GREAT IDEA
CAME FROM JOE SR.,
WHO TOOK OVER HIS FATHER'S
CHICKEN JOINT IN 1968.
WE DON'T LIKE TO WASTE ANYTHING,
AND THEY TURNED OUT TO BE
QUITE A DEAL.
EXPLAIN EXACTLY WHAT
THE GIZZARD IS TO ME.
IT'S A GRINDER.
IT'S LIKE A SECOND STOMACH.
YOU'RE NOT EATING THE WORKING
PART OF THE STOMACH.
GOOD, 'CAUSE I DON'T LIKE
ANYTHING THAT HAS A JOB.
NO.
OH, SO THAT'S
THE MUSCLE OF IT.
THE MUSCLE OF IT, YEAH.
THE MUSCLE AROUND HERE
IS JOE JR.,
WHO'S TAKEN OVER
FOR HIS DAD.
I WAS WORKIN' THROUGH
THE CORPORATE STRUCTURE.
(Guy) OF RESTAURANTS?
ABOUT SEVEN,
EIGHT YEARS AGO DECIDED,
YOU KNOW, IT'S TIME TO COME
BACK AND WORK FOR THE FAMILY.
AND TAKE OVER
THE GIZZARD EMPIRE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S GNARLY.
WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA
PRESSURE-COOK THE GIZZARDS.
AND WHY?
YOU HAVE TO TENDERIZE
THE GIZZARD,
OR ELSE IT'S GONNA TASTE
LIKE SHOE LEATHER.
SO THAT'S WHY MOST PEOPLE
DON'T EAT GIZZARDS AT HOME.
CORRECT.
WHAT SEASONINGS
DO WE PUT IN IT?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
HAVE GARLIC POWDER,
CELERY SALT AND SALT.
NOW WE LOCK AND LOAD?
LOCK AND LOAD, BABY.
(imitates pressure cooker)
(Guy) DON'T THOSE
LOOK PRECIOUS?
(gags)
JOES FAMOUS BATTER MIX.
NOW WHAT IS THIS?
SPECIAL FLOUR.
WHERE'S IT COME FROM?
UH, I CAN'T
TELL YOU THAT.
IT HAS, LIKE, A CORNSTARCH
CONSISTENCY,
BUT IT'S NOT CORNSTARCH.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT--
IT'S A SPECIAL FLOUR.
THANKS A LOT.
SO IF I FIGURED OUT
THIS ONE...
I'M GONNA TAKE SOME OF THAT
HOME WITH ME AND FIND OUT.
NOW WATER?
I'M GONNA GET YOU A MIXER
FOR CHRISTMAS.
OH, PLEASE.
(imitates Hans and Franz)
THIS ARM IS BEEFING UP.
LOOK AT THAT, LIKE A PYTHON
GOING TO SNAP AT YOU.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
(normal voice)
I DIDN'T NEED THAT MANY.
I DON'T WANT TO WASTE.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
WANT MORE THAN THIS.
BURN, BABY, BURN.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
YES.
I DON'T WANT TO BE A HOG
AND HAVE 'EM ALL.
SERIOUSLY, SAVE SOME
FOR YOURSELF.
AH, YOU'LL--
YOU'LL LOVE THIS.
MMM.
THAT'S TENDER.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK--I THINK THEY'RE
QUITE TASTY, ACTUALLY.
I THINK THE SEASONING THAT
YOU PRESSURE-COOK THEM IN--
THAT MAKES
A BIG DIFFERENCE.
THE BATTER IS--
IS KILLER.
DON'T GET GIZZARDS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
THESE GIZZARDS
ARE THE BEST!
AND DEEP-FRYIN'
AIN'T YOUR ONLY OPTION.
NAKED CAJUN GIZZARDS.
I GOT THE GARLIC AND HERB,
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
HEY, PUT 'EM IN AN OMELET.
IS THAT A GIGANTIC GIZZARD?
THAT'S A PIECE OF CHICKEN.
I GOT THE COMBO PLATE.
IT'S THE BEST OF BOTH WORLDS.
OH, YOU CAN?
YOU CAN GET THE OUTSIDE--
OUTSIDE AND INSIDE.
YOU GET THE OUTSIDE/
INSIDE.
THE OUTSIDE IS WHAT GOT
THIS PLACE ROLLIN'.
WHO TAUGHT YOU HOW
TO MAKE FRIED CHICKEN?
UH, MY GRANDMOTHER.
WHAT'S THE KEY TO MAKING
GREAT FRIED CHICKEN?
YOU GOTTA KEEP IT JUICY,
AND YOU GOTTA BOIL IT.
NEXT WE HAVE OUR
GARLIC POWDER.
YOU GOTTA LOVE GARLIC.
MM-HMM. CELERY SALT.
OKAY, SO YOU COOK THE CHICKEN
JUST TO WHERE IT'S DONE...
CORRECT.
THEN WE'LL BATTER IT,
AND THEN WE'LL FRY IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
DIG IT. LET'S SEE IT.
OH, THAT JUST COATS
RIGHT ON THERE.
IS THAT GOLDEN
SUPER DELICIOUS?
OH, YEP.
WOW.
AH...
IT'S, UH, SUPER TENDER
AND MOIST.
MY GOSH, IT FALLS APART.
YOU KNOW THE FIRST THING
I GET OUT OF THAT?
WHAT'S THAT?
IS THAT GARLIC FLAVOR
OF THAT CHICKEN
WHEN IT BOILED.
MMM.
SURE IS A DIFFERENT WAY
TO DO CHICKEN.
THANK YOU.
(man) ONLY AT JOE'S.
THEY'RE BIG ON DIFFERENT HERE,
LIKE DEEP-FRIED HOT DOGS
WITH MELTED CHEESE.
THESE ARE...
DEEP-FRIED OREOS.
THEY ARE SO GOOD.
EVEN DEEP-FRIED TWINKIES.
THEY CALL 'EM FRINKIES.
YEAH.
THAT MIGHT BE ILLEGAL
TO SERVE.
I MEAN, THAT'S FREAKY.
BUT IF YOU WANT FREAKY,
HOW 'BOUT A DEEP-FRIED BURGER?
SO YOU SAID,
"LET'S COOK THE BURGER..."
YEAH.
"AND THEN LET'S BATTER IT,
AND THEN LET'S FRY IT..."
YEAH.
"AND PUT IT IN A BURGER."
YEP.
(Guy)I GOTTA TELL YOU,
THERE'S A FEW THINGS
THAT I DON'T THINK
I'D EVER SEEN BEFORE.
DEEP-FRIED PATTY IN BATTER.
MMM, I LIKE THAT.
YOU DO TASTE THE CRUNCH,
AND IT ALSO CHANGES
THE FLAVOR OF
THE MEAT A LITTLE BIT.
I'D GET IT THAT WAY VERSUS
THE REGULAR WAY.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
CRUNCHY?
A LITTLE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE...
(man) SOFT AND JUICY
ON THE INSIDE.
SOFT AND JUICY
YOU GUYS SOUNDS LIKE
YOU'RE DOIN' COMMERCIALS.
BUT AS GOOD AS THAT IS,
WHY FRY JUST THE BURGER?
LET'S BATTER THE WHOLE THING,
BUN AND ALL.
NOW...
FIRST TIME EVER PERFORMED
HERE AT GIZZARD CITY.
(chuckling)
OH, YUMMY.
YEP.
OH.
HOPE IT DON'T FALL APART.
(laughing)
LET'S CUT IT
OUT OF ITS TOMB.
LOOK... AT... THAT.
MMM.
WOW.
TERRIFIC.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
IT IS MONEY.
JOE'S PUT IT ON THE MENU NOW,
AS THE TRIPLE D BURGER.
SERIOUSLY, I WOULD ORDER ONE OF
THOSE EVERY TIME I CAME IN HERE.
COOL.
ALONG WITH
A GIZZARD APPETIZER
AND A FRINKIE DESSERT.
EVERYTHING AT JOE'S IS GOOD.
JOE AND JOEY HAVE ALWAYS
HAD SOMETHING UNIQUE.
HOW MANY RESTAURANTS SPECIALIZE
IN GIZZARDS? I DON'T KNOW.
GET YOUR GIZZARD FIX
AT EXIT 66.
IS THAT WHERE WE ARE?
YES, YOU ARE.
♪ WELL I'M GOIN'
DOWN TO JOE'S ♪
(whispers) JOE'S!
♪ DOWN TO GIZZARD CITY ♪
JOE'S! JOE'S!
THIS PLACE IS A TRIP.
THANK YOU.
I'D TAKE THAT
AS A COMPLIMENT.
UP NEXT...
(bell rings)
A ONE-OF-A-KIND DINER
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
OH, MAN.
WHERE THIS GUY'S GROWIN' IT...
(man) I GROW
IN MY GARDEN.
AND COOKIN' IT
THE WAY HIS MOM DID
BACK IN PORTUGAL.
PORTUGUESI-AMERICANI.
"PORTUGUESI-AMERICANI"
DID YOU SAY?
SAN FRANCISCO
IS SUCH A KILLER TOWN.
YOU GOT THE GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE,
FISHERMAN'S WHARF,
CABLE CARS
AND GREAT ETHNIC FOOD.
NOW YOU KNOW
A FOOD HOUND LIKE ME
LOVES WHEN YOU CAN GET
TWO OF THESE AT THE SAME TIME.
CHECK IT OUT--A CABLE CAR
WITH PORTUGUESE FOOD.
THIS PLACE
IS ONE OF A KIND.
(bell rings)
(woman) WONDERFUL SOUP--
SOME LINGUIçA AND SOME KALE.
FOR FERNANDO SANTOS,
HIS DINER FOOD'S THE STUFF
HE GREW UP WITH IN PORTUGAL...
MOST OF THE COOKING
IS FROM MY MOM.
LIKE COD AND POTATOES
WITH FRESH CURED OLIVES.
(grunts)
THESE GUYS ARE FROM PORTUGAL.
THEY KNOW ALL ABOUT FISH.
PORK CHOPS WITH OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC AND ROASTED RED PEPPER,
AND A SPICY SAUSAGE
CALLED LINGUIçA.
OH, WOW.
YOU GUYS ALL BEEN
HERE BEFORE?
YES.
YES, YES.
FOLKS HAVE BEEN HANGIN' HERE
SINCE 1927
WHEN THE PLACE OPENED
IN A REAL-DEAL CABLE CAR.
THIS WAS FROM KEY LINE.
AND THEY RETIRED IT.
FERNANDO BOUGHT IT IN '89...
(speaking Portuguese)
AND MET HIS WIFE LINDA HERE
WHEN SHE CAME INTO EAT
AND COMPLAINED
ABOUT HAVIN' TO WAIT.
YOU GOT A DATE OUT OF A GUEST
THAT WAS GONNA COMPLAIN?
YOU'RE SMOOTH!
NOW THEY'RE RUNNIN'
THE PLACE TOGETHER,
AND FERNANDO'S COOKIN'
LIKE HE'S BACK HOME.
I'M GONNA GET
THE PORK CHOP.
THE PORTUGUESE
CHOPS, RIGHT?
I LOVE PORK CHOPS.
I LOVE PORK.
BEFORE IT GOES IN THE PAN,
I HAVE SOME SAUCE HERE,
AND IT'S OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, PAPRIKA,
CUMIN AND RED WINE.
OH-HO, LOOK AT THAT.
WHERE DO YOU WANT THE POTATOES?
ON THE PLATE?
PUT THESE RIGHT ON PLATE.
NOW YOU DO THE PORK CHOPS.
THAT IS A HUNK
OF BROCCOLI.
AND MORE CABBAGE.
AND THEN I GET
THE RED BELL PEPPERS?
THERE YOU GO.
'KAY, WHERE DO YOU
WANT THOSE?
RIGHT ON TOP
OF THE VEGETABLES.
RIGHT ON TOP OF THAT
SO IT'S NICE AND PRETTY?
THERE YOU GO.
HA-HA!
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
NOW THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
AH. OH.
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
GREAT.
I COULD EAT
A BUNCH OF THAT.
I REALLY COULD.
THAT'S--
YOU DIDN'T WANT
A BITE, DID YOU?
UH...
GOOD.
THE PORTUGUESE TAKE ON CHOPS
AND ON STEAKS
HAS BEEN A BIG HIT
AT THIS JOINT,
AND SO HAVE SOME OTHER DISHES
THAT MOST FOLKS
HAD NEVER SEEN BEFORE,
LIKE SOMETHING THEY
DO WITH CODFISH.
SO IS THIS A TRADITIONAL DISH?
I MEAN...
YES.
A LOT OF PORTUGAL--
THERE'S A LOT OF SEAFOOD?
YES.
THIS IS THE CODFISH
I'VE BEEN SOAKING OVERNIGHT
IN WATER.
SO WE'RE GOING TO BOIL THIS
FOR A MINUTE.
WE'RE GOING TO PUT
THE GARLIC IN THE FRYING PAN.
ONIONS GO IN?
NOW WE HAVE
BOILED POTATOES.
WE'RE GOING TO CHOP
THE CODFISH RIGHT IN.
EGG. WE GOT
A LITTLE MORE PEPPER.
CURLY PARSLEY.
YES.
AND NOW GOES THE OLIVES.
I CURE THE OLIVES.
REALLY?
MY MOM'S RECIPE.
HOW 'BOUT SOME GREEN SAUCE?
GREEN SAUCE WOULD BE GOOD.
"VERDE FIRE SAUCE."
UH-HUH!
UH-HUH.
(laughs)
THAT IS GOOD.
IT'S GREAT.
IT REMINDS ME OF SOMETHING
THAT'S VERY SPANISH.
BUT DON'T GO EXPLAINING IT
THAT WAY TO SANTOS,
WHO'S SO INTO HIS
PORTUGUESE MENU...
THIS IS A PORTUGUESE WINE.
THAT HE'S GOT THE LOCALS
ORDERING BY COLOR.
THEY'LL SAY CALDO VERDE.
THAT MEANS GREEN SOUP.
SOME LINGUIçA
AND SOME KALE.
IT'S WONDERFUL SOUP.
IT'S A PORTUGUESE KALE.
PORTUGUESE KALE.
YES. I GROW IN MY--
IN MY GARDEN.
THIS IS YOURS?
YES.
WHERE'S THIS FROM?
PORTUGAL?
PORTUGAL, YES.
SEE, YOU CAN DO IT.
I LIKE THE HANDLE.
JUST DROP IT IN.
ALL AT ONE TIME?
THERE WE GO.
THE CHICKEN STOCK WAS COOKED
TOGETHER WITH THE LINGUIçA--
PORTUGUESE SAUSAGE.
OH, I LOVE--
WE SHOULD PROBABLY TRY THAT.
OKAY.
MMM. AW, MAN.
(Fernando) HOW IS THAT?
WHAT IS THAT OVER THERE.
(laughs)
REGULAR RUSSET POTATO?
DUMP IT IN NOW.
OKAY, I DON'T THINK YOUR MOM
HAD THIS IN HER KITCHEN.
IT'S SMALLER.
YOU HAVE A LICENSE FOR THIS?
NOW WE PUT THE KALE IN?
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE KALE IN.
AND NOW GOES THE SAUSAGE.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHY ONLY TWO PIECES?
OH-OH. OKAY.
DO THE WHOLE THING!
EXTRA PIECE.
OKAY, LET'S DO IT.
DOUBLE.
THERE GOES THE KALE.
AND IT GOES ON TOP
LIKE THAT.
YEP.
MMM, YUMMY.
IT'S YUMMY!
YUMMY.
NOT A WORD I OFTEN USE,
BUT NOW THAT I'M HANGING
WITH YOU, SANTOS,
YUMMY!
NOW SANTOS IS ALSO DOING
A FULL MENU
OF AMERICAN DINER BASICS HERE.
BUT EVEN SOME OF THOSE
GET A SANTOS TWIST,
LIKE AN EGG
ON THE CHEESEBURGER...
IT LOOKS ODD,
BUT IT TASTES GOOD.
AND PORTUGUESE MARINADE
ON THE WINGS.
THE SAUCE IS MONEY.
IT'S PORTUGUESI-AMERICANI.
"PORTUGUESI-AMERICANI"
DID YOU SAY?
(laughter)
THAT'S WHAT THE WHOLE PLACE
IS ABOUT,
WITH HOME COOKIN'
LIKE MOM USED TO MAKE,
ONLY MOM'S FROM PORTUGAL.
I COULD HAVE THIS
EVERY DAY.
CAN I TASTE IT
FOR YOU?
AND LIKE ANY CLASSIC DINER,
WHATEVER THE MENU,
IT'S A PLACE YOU WANT TO COME
BACK TO ANY TIME OF DAY.
AND DO YOU TYPICALLY
WORK TOGETHER,
OR DOES ONE TYPICALLY OPEN AND
THE OTHER PERSON CLOSES?
I OPEN, HE CLOSES.
WHEN DO YOU GUYS
SEE EACH OTHER?
WE DON'T. THAT'S WHY OUR
MARRIAGE IS SO GOOD.
NEXT UP...
(Guy) THAT'S MONDO
A DETOUR WORTH TAKIN'...
(man) THE SALSA'S FRESH.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
BY THE SIDE OF THE HIGHWAY.
THAT'S KILLER.
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA IS KNOWN
FOR A LOT OF THINGS.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES
IS MEXICAN FOOD,
AND NOT JUST ANY
OLD MEXICAN FOOD--
TACO TRUCKS, LIKE THIS BROTHER
AND SISTER TEAM WE FOUND
IN SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA,
RIGHT OFF HIGHWAY 101.
HOLA!
16 TACO, BABY.
EVERYTHING'S FOR HERE.
YOU GUYS ARE
BUILT FOR SPEED.
GREAT FOOD.
GREAT SERVICE.
YOU AND ME IN HERE GOIN'
IN OPPOSITE DIRECTIONS--
THIS THING IS LIKE WE'RE
ON A PIRATE SHIP. ARR!
LOS TAPATIOS IS PIRATE SHIP
WITH A RIGHTEOUS MENU,
'CAUSE BROTHER
AND SISTER OWNERS,
DANIEL AND DEISSY GONZALES
LEARNED THEIR COOKING
FROM THE EXPERTS.
MY GODMOTHER,
MY GRANDMA, AND MY MOTHER.
THE RESULT WAS EVERYTHING FROM
BASIC TACOS AND BURRITOS
TO TRADITIONAL BEEF
AND PORK DISHES,
LIKE CARNE ASADA
AND CARNITAS,
A PORK AND VEGGIE SANDWICH...
THAT'S KILLER.
AND SOME DISHES SO AUTHENTIC,
YOU JUST WONT FIND 'EM
AT MOST PLACES.
BUCHE? WHAT'S THAT?
THAT'S A STOMACH.
OH, YES,
I ALWAYS ENJOY
A NICE STOMACH.
NOW WHO MAKES THE SALSA?
(David) MY GODMOTHER DOES.
IT'S ALL PUT TOGETHER IN ANY
COMBINATION YOU WANT.
"ONE B.S.A.C.I.T."?
ONE BURRITO SUPER ASADA
CON TODO--
WITH EVERYTHING.
CON TODO.
TOTALLY CON TODO.
I COULD HIDE
BEHIND THIS, DUDE.
OKAY, SO WE HIT
THE GUACAMOLE.
THE GUAC, RICE.
THEN BEANS?
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
CARNE ASADA.
THAT'S MONDO.
5 BUCKS
IS ALL THAT IS?
YEAH.
WE'VE BEEN HERE
SO LONG ALREADY,
THEY KNOW EVERYTHING
IS FRESH.
AND DONE THE HOMEMADE WAY.
ANYTHING IN A SOFT TORTILLA,
AND THE PROCESS STARTS HERE.
SO YOU DIP IT
IN THE MANTECA...
LARD, THANK YOU.
OH, YOU PADDLE IT
ON WITH THEM. UH-HUH.
THOSE TORTILLAS ARE GONNA
GET PRETTY CRISPY.
AND LOAD 'EM UP WITH ANYTHING.
UH, ONIONS AND CILANTRO.
THAT'S SOME BOMB GRILLED
CHICKEN.
THE RED SALSA.
THE KICKER IS THE LITTLE
CRISPING OF IT.
THAT SALSA'S PRETTY MONEY.
YEAH.
WELL, I MEAN, THE TOMATOES--
FRESH TOMATOES.
THEY GET ROASTED
IN THE MORNING.
I WOULD EAT HERE
EVERY DAY.
WE HAVE THOSE
KIND OF CUSTOMERS.
HEY, DON'T LET THIS SCARE YOU
THAT YOU GOT
SOME BLOND-HAIR WETO
MAKIN' THIS.
THE SALSA'S FRESH.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
WHAT'S THE FUTURE
FOR TAPATIOS?
IT'S IN THE WORKS
RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL HAVE SEVICHES.
WE'LL HAVE SHRIMP COCKTAILS,
CAMPECHANAS WITH
THE OCTOPUS AND EVERYTHING.
WE WANT THAT.
(laughs)
YOU KNOW, SOMETHING A LITTLE
DIFFERENT, YOU KNOW?
"YES, AND WHERE
ARE YOU TODAY?"
"OH, I'M HAVING SEVICHE
BY THE 880 AND 101
"IN CALIFORNIA
IN SAN JOSE.
"YEAH, MEET ME HERE.
I HAVE RESERVATIONS
FOR THE MIDDLE BENCH."
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
AH, YOU'LL--
YOU'LL LOVE THIS.
(laughs)
IT'S LIKE JUMPING
IN COLD WATER.
I CAN'T DO IT YET.
COME ON!