HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(man) AND THERE WE GO.
(Guy)
THIS TRIP--TOTALLY TURKEY.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
THE BOSTON DINER
WHERE IT'S THANKSGIVING
EVERY DAY OF THE WEEK...
TURKEY'S FANTASTIC.
WHERE THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
FOUR OF THESE EVERY DAY...
I WAS LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
HE'S GOT REAL TURKEYS
UP THERE ON THE BONE."
ARE YOU GUYS GETTIN'
ENOUGH TO EAT?
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA'S
KING OF THE TURKEYS
AND HIS TOTALLY
TURKEY RESTAURANT...
90% OF THE MENU IS TURKEY.
TURKEY RATES AT THE TOP.
WHERE THEY'LL TURN TURKEY
INTO ANYTHING...
(Guy) HOW IS THE SCALOPPINE?
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
AND THE FLORIDA JOINT
THAT'S TAKIN' TURKEY
TOTALLY OUT OF BOUNDS...
HOLY MOLY.
STUFFING IT WITH DUCK
AND CHICKEN TO MAKE TURDUCKEN.
I LOVE IT,
ALL THE DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
YOU GOTTA GET A TASTE
OF THIS ONE.
THAT'S LIKE SOMEONE SHOT OFF
ALL THE FIREWORKS
AT THE SAME TIME.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN I THINK OF BOSTON,
I THINK OF THE TEA PARTY,
I THINK OF THE SOX, OF COURSE,
AND NOW A PLACE CALLED
MIKE'S CITY DINER.
THAT'S NOT BECAUSE
THE OWNER'S AN IMMIGRANT
LIVING THE AMERICAN DREAM
OR BECAUSE PRESIDENT CLINTON'S
EATEN HERE.
IT'S BECAUSE OF THE WAY
THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
AN AMERICAN FAVORITE--TURKEY.
HERE YOU GO, FOLKS.
ALL RIGHT, JAY.
WOW, THANK YOU, JAY.
TURKEY'S FANTASTIC.
FOOD IS JUST AMAZING.
DID YOU SEE THIS PLATE?
THAT SHOULD BE
ALMOST SEMI-ILLEGAL.
(woman) AND I REMEMBER
THE FIRST TIME I CAME IN HERE.
I SAID, "IS THAT REAL
OR IS THAT A PROP?"
OH, IT'S REAL, ALL RIGHT,
ONE OF FOUR HOME-COOKED TURKEYS
THEY'RE DOIN' UP AND SERVIN' UP
EVERY DAY HERE.
THE ALL AMERICAN MEAL...
NICE TO MEET YOU.
FROM A GUY WHO'S TELLIN' YA
HE'S LIVIN'
THE ALL-AMERICAN DREAM.
HOW OLD WERE YOU WHEN
YOU CAME TO THE STATES?
8. 8 YEARS OLD.
8 YEARS OLD,
AND YOU CAME FROM...
LEBANON.
JAY HAJJ FELL INTO THE FOOD BIZ
AS A DISHWASHER IN HIS TEENS.
THEN WORKED HIS WAY UP.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
HE BOUGHT THIS PLACE
12 YEARS AGO,
LEFT THE ORIGINAL NAME,
BUT GOT RIGHT TO WORK
ON HIS OWN MENU...
CAN I HAVE SOME
MORE FRIES?
FILLED WITH FRESH,
HOMEMADE LOCAL FAVORITES.
WE GOT SOME GOOD
TURKEY DINNER TODAY.
WHEN HE TRIED HIS HAND AT
TURKEY, IT WAS AN INSTANT HIT.
IT KIND OF HAPPENED
BY ACCIDENT.
I HAD NO PLACE TO PUT
THE TURKEYS BUT ON THE STEAMER,
ON TOP OF THE STEAMER,
AND BECAUSE IT WAS AN OPEN
KITCHEN, JUST IT GREW.
IT JUST GOT OUT OF CONTROL.
I WAS LIKE, "OH, MY GOD.
HE'S GOT REAL TURKEYS
UP THERE ON THE BONE."
...AND ON THE PLATE
AND IN HUGE SANDWICHES,
TURKEY SALAD, TURKEY MEATLOAF,
TURKEY EVERYTHING
ALL MADE FRESH EVERY DAY...
(Jay) HERE WE GO.
GRAB 'EM NOW.
JAY'S WAY.
SO SOMEONE MADE THAT FOR YA.
YEAH.
THAT'S--DUDE, THAT'S SNAZZY.
WHERE'D YOU GET THE IDEA?
I MEAN, I'VE DONE
THE BEER-CAN CHICKEN.
YEARS AGO, I FOUND THE STAND
FOR THE CHICKEN--
EXACTLY,
THE BEER-CAN CHICKEN--
AND I REALIZED THAT IT COOKS
THE CHICKEN A LITTLE BETTER,
'CAUSE IT'S COOKING FROM
THE INSIDE AND THE OUTSIDE.
YOU PUSH THE WINGS
RIGHT IN THE BACK.
I LIKE THIS
LITTLE MANEUVER.
PUT YOUR WINGS
BEHIND YOUR BACK!
THERE WE GO.
AND WE'RE NOT
GONNA SEASON THIS.
NO SEASONING.
NO SEASONING
UNDER THE SKIN?
UNLESS YOU WANT
TO EAT THE SKIN,
I'VE FOUND THAT IT DOESN'T
GIVE ANY EXTRA FLAVORS
FOR THE MEAT,
BUT IF YOU SAY SO,
I WILL AGREE WITH YOU.
NO NEED.
JAY'S GONNA BE ALL OVER
THIS SEASONING THING
WITH HIS HOMEMADE GRAVY.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW THIS IS ONION POWDER,
GARLIC AND WHITE PEPPER.
THAT IS FOR THE STOCK.
A LITTLE BAY LEAF?
YEP.
TURKISH OR CALIFORNIAN?
THAT'S CALIFORNIAN.
CALIFORNIAN.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA MAKE
A STANDARD ROUX.
THERE WE GO.
YEAH, COME TO PAPA.
YOU WHISK THAT SO YOU DON'T MAKE
YOURSELF ANY, UH, DUMPLINGS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S GOT REAL BIG FLAVOR.
THE STUFFING WILL, TOO.
CELERY, CARROTS--
JUST DUMP 'EM IN?
DUMP 'EM RIGHT IN.
WE'RE NOT GONNA
SAUTé 'EM OR ANYTHING?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
THAT'S FOR FANCY PLACES.
WHITE ONION?
WHITE ONION.
SPANISH ONION, YEP.
I DIDN'T TALK TO IT.
HOW'D YOU KNOW IT WAS SPANISH?
NOW THE TURKEY. LITTLE CHUNKS
BETWEEN THE STUFFING.
THE WHITE PEPPER, CUMIN,
THE SEASONED SALT
AND THE POULTRY
SEASONING.
WHISK.
WHISK A LITTLE BIT,
AND NOW WE LET IT SIMMER FOR
ABOUT FIVE--FIVE, TEN MINUTES.
WE DON'T WANT TO BREAK
THE VEGGIES DOWN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
PUT IT RIGHT IN HERE.
WOW.
AND NOW I'M GONNA
SMASH 'EM OUT.
NOW WE GOTTA BAKE THIS.
IT'S NOT DONE. THERE WE GO.
AND THERE ARE POTATOES TO MASH
AND SQUASH TO WHIP UP.
NOW WHIPPIN' IT WITH A WHIP
KEEPS IT A LITTLE STRINGY.
YOU WANT IT
A LITTLE STRINGY.
EVERYTHING YOU DO HAS GOT
A LITTLE MAGIC BEHIND IT.
BUT THE REAL MAGIC...
HERE WE GO.
IS WHEN IT'S ALL ON ONE PLATE.
WOW. THE TURKEY'S
SUPER MONEY TENDER,
AND THE GRAVY,
WHICH IS MONEY...
STUFFING--
CAN STILL TASTE THE TEXTURE
OF THE VEGETABLES,
BUT IT'S CREAMY.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
HAVE YOU EATEN
THE THANKSGIVING-ATHON
HERE BEFORE?
THANKSGIVING IN JULY.
YEAH, THANKSGIVING
IN SEPTEMBER, FEBRUARY,
ABOUT ANYTIME YOU WANT IT.
WELL, THAT'S ONE
OF THE COOL THINGS.
YOU GET IT
ANYTIME YOU WANT.
AND IF THANKSGIVING ON A PLATE
ISN'T YOUR THING...
THOSE ARE OUR PILGRIM
SANDWICHES, YOU GUYS.
(man) THAT'S LIKE
THANKSGIVING DINNER.
THAT'S RIGHT. IT IS
THANKSGIVING ALL IN A ROLL.
WE GOTTA MAKE
A PILGRIM SANDWICH.
OKAY. OKAY, SO CRANBERRIES.
PUT STUFFING IN IT.
THAT'S A NICE GIDDYAP.
USUALLY, IT'S ALL WHITE MEAT,
UNLESS THE CUSTOMER ASKS FOR...
SO YOU PRETTY MUCH MAKE AND DO
AND GIVE WHATEVER THEY WANT?
THEY WANT.
HOLY ENCHILADA.
HOW MUCH YOU GONNA GIVE 'EM?
YOU SHOULD CALL THAT
SANDWICH THE "GOOD NIGHT."
HOW MANY OF THESE
YOU SELL A DAY?
ABOUT 45, I WOULD SAY.
45 A DAY?
45, 50, YEAH.
NO WONDER YOU GO THROUGH
700,000 TURKEYS A YEAR.
NOW DO YOU EAT THIS
WITH A--
IS THERE, LIKE,
A CONTRAPTION?
WELL, WHEN THERE'S
GRAVY IN IT,
IT'S BEST TO EAT IT
WITH A FORK AND KNIFE.
I GOT THE GRAVY,
THE STUFFING.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THANKS.
THAT STANDS UP THERE IN
THE BEST TURKEY SANDWICHES
I'VE EVER HAD.
WOW.
HERE GOES THE CHAMPIONSHIP
BITE. LOOK AT THAT.
DID YOU HEAR A PIGGY NOISE
WHEN HE BIT INTO IT?
(snorts)
COME ON, SAY "EAT 'EM UP."
(girls) EAT THEM UP!
I LIKE IT ALL MIXED UP,
JUST LIKE THANKSGIVING.
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
IS THIS FOR REAL? LET ME GET
ANOTHER GUY TO HELP ME EAT IT.
IT'S LIKE THAT WITH EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU HERE--
HUGE PORTIONS
OF REAL-DEAL COOKIN'...
EGGS BENEDICT...
YEP.
WITH A HUGE CHUNK OF HAM.
THAT HAS FOLKS LININ' UP.
(Guy) DO YOU EAT IT ALL?
UH, I MAKE A GOOD--
I MAKE A GOOD DENT ON IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE'S NO GUT DOWN THERE.
DYNAMIC DUO, AND THEN I GET
EGGS AND SAUSAGE FOR EXTRA.
THIS IS CALLED
THE DYNAMIC DUO?
UH-HUH.
WELL, THEY USUALLY ORDER THEM
BEFORE I SIT DOWN, SO...
SO YOU'RE THAT LOYAL.
YEAH.
GRETCHEN, AMANDA!
FOR JAY...
AND HOW'S YOUR BREAKFAST
THIS MORNING?
IT'S ALL ABOUT OWNING A PLACE
PEOPLE WANT TO COME TO...
THAT.
I'M VERY PROUD OF THAT.
AND LOCALS WANT
TO KEEP COMING BACK TO...
EVERYTHING IS GOOD?
PERFECT.
AND A BIG PART OF THAT IS
BASIC AMERICAN HOME COOKIN',
LIKE THOSE FOUR TURKEYS A DAY--
THANKSGIVING ANYTIME YOU WANT.
REALLY, I MEAN,
THAT'S A SERVING.
GET ANOTHER PLATE.
SEE, THIS IS WHAT I LOVE. THIS
IS THE BEST THING ABOUT THIS.
DUDE, YOU ARE
THE AMERICAN DREAM.
I AM.
I FEEL SOMETIME LIKE IT'S
LIKE WINNING A LOTTERY TICKET.
IT IS.
GET THE HAND CART.
I'M READY TO GET TO MY CAR.
HOW'S THAT DRUMSTICK?
COMING UP...
CAN YOU MAKE A TURKEY CALL?
(imitates turkey gobble)
WE'RE HEADING
TO NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
TO A JOINT THAT'LL MAKE
ANYTHING OUT OF TURKEY.
HOW'S THE STROGANOFF?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
ON THIS LEG
OF OUR TALKIN' TURKEY TOUR,
I'M IN MY OWN BACKYARD
OF SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA,
AT A PLACE CALLED WILLIE BIRD'S
WHERE THERE REALLY IS A WILLIE,
AND WHEN IT COMES TO TURKEY,
HE DOES IT ALL... I MEAN, ALL.
THAT'S A BIG EAT, MAN.
IT'S TURKEY, GRAVY,
CRANBERRY SAUCE.
CHEESE, TURKEY AND HAM.
HOW'S THAT DRUMSTICK?
TURKEY STEAK
DINNER SANDWICH.
I GO FOR THE TURKEY,
SIMPLE AS THAT.
ARE YOU GUYS GETTIN'
ENOUGH TO EAT? HUH?
GREAT.
TURKEY RATES AT THE TOP.
THAT'S JUST FLAT-OUT.
90% OF THE MENU IS TURKEY.
IT'S A WORLD OF TURKEY.
FROM ITALY--
TURKEY SCALOPPINE...
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
TURKEY PARMESAN AND ITALIAN
TURKEY SAUSAGE SANDWICH.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
FROM RUSSIA--TURKEY STROGANOFF.
HOW'S THE STROGANOFF?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
FROM COWBOY COUNTRY--
TURKEY-FRIED STEAK.
IF YOU HAVE AN APPETITE,
BRING IT WITH YOU.
WORLD-FAMOUS TURKEY--
CAN'T GET WRONG WITH THAT.
WE COME HERE
ALL THE TIME.
DO YOU?
IT LOOKS LIKE
GRANDMA'S HOUSE.
THE REASON IT'S SO GOOD--
WILLIE'S NOT JUST RUNNING
A TURKEY RESTAURANT OUT HERE
IN THE WINE COUNTRY...
ENJOY.
HE'S RUNNIN' A TURKEY FARM.
HOW MANY TURKEYS
ARE YOU RAISING?
100,000.
100,000?
HOW DO YOU COUNT THAT HIGH?
TAKE BOTH SHOES OFF?
WILLIE STARTED OUT IN '63
WITH 250 TURKEYS.
TODAY, THAT'S BECOME
A TURKEY EMPIRE,
SELLING 100,000 TURKEYS A YEAR.
AND, OF COURSE, THERE'S
WILLIE BIRD'S RESTAURANT.
HOW YOU LADIES DOING?
YOU ENJOYING YOUR MEAL?
THEY CALL ME
"THE BIG BIRD."
DO THEY CALL YOU--THE BOYS
CALL YOU "THE BIG BIRD?"
YEAH, "THE BIG BIRD."
FROM THE '80s AND '90s,
PER CAPITA CONSUMPTION OF TURKEY
JUST WENT THROUGH THE ROOF.
WE OPENED THE RESTAURANT
TO SHOW HOW IT COULD BE
COOKED AND PREPARED.
LIKE THAT TURKEY STROGANOFF.
STROGANOFF.
FOLKS AROUND HERE LOVE IT.
TURKEY THIGH.
YEP, TURKEY THIGH.
IT'S BEEN TENDERIZED.
CUT IT UP. GARLIC SALT.
DROP IT IN THERE.
TOSS IT AROUND A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE OFF TO THE STOVE.
SHOW ME YOUR MAGIC.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S HOT OIL.
COOK IT UP A LITTLE BIT,
CRUST IT.
WE GOT TURKEY BROTH.
HERE COMES THE ONIONS,
THE MUSHROOMS.
THE GARLIC.
THE WORCESTERSHIRE.
NOW WE COOK THIS DOWN,
THEN WE THROW THE SHERRY IN.
WE'RE READY TO ADD
THE SOUR CREAM.
YOU JUST POUR IT
OVER THE TOP.
AND THIS IS HOW
IT COMES OUT THERE?
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT.
MM-HMM. MMM. MMM.
I'M IMPRESSED.
THAT'S MONEY, DUDE, REALLY.
YOU'RE GONNA SEE ME BACK
JUST FOR THIS ONE.
OR MAYBE
FOR THE TURKEY SCALOPPINE.
(Guy)
HOW IS THE SCALOPPINE?
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
IT IS FANTASTIC, ISN'T IT?
THIS IS GONNA BE DIFFERENT
THAN THE STROGANOFF.
RIGHT.
THIS IS THE WHITE MEAT NOW.
ONIONS AND THE GARLIC.
ONIONS AND GARLIC.
WHAT IS THIS
WE JUST DID HERE?
WE'RE PUTTIN' IN MARSALA.
A LITTLE MARSALA WINE
GOES DOWN.
AND BEYOND USING TURKEY...
I'M IN IT, WILLIE.
THERE'S ONE MORE TWIST.
USUALLY WHEN YOU THINK
SCALOPPINE, YOU THINK SLICES.
YEP.
THESE ARE CHUNKS.
MMM. CRISPY, CRUNCHY, YUMMY?
YEP.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S GOT GOOD FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT JUST TENDER.
IT'S MEATY.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
I THINK DIFFERENT.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE EXPECT
THAT ALL THE TIME
TURKEY'S ALWAYS SLICED
AND ALL THAT.
THIS HAS GOT A REAL NICE
MEATY CHEW TO IT.
THAT IS TASTY.
POLISHED EVERYTHING
OFF ALREADY, HUH?
WILLIE'S GOT A TWIST OF HIS OWN
FOR EVERY DISH...
THAT TURKEY'S KEEPIN' YA YOUNG
AND BEAUTIFUL. CAN YOU SEE THAT?
LIKE HIS TURKEY VERSION
OF CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
THEN IT GOES INTO THE--
CHECK OUT THE EGG WASH.
I'M USIN' TURKEY EGGS.
WE JUST HAPPENED TO HAVE SOME.
YOU ARE NOT.
YEP, TURKEY EGGS.
AND THAT'S GONNA BE BETTER THAN
CHICKEN CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
OH, YOU BETCHA.
THAT'S LOOKIN' GOOD.
YEAH, LOOKIN' GOOD.
AND THERE WE HAVE--
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
OH, LOOK AT HOW PERFECT
I PUT THAT ON THERE, HUH?
MMM. THAT'S TASTY.
IT'S GOT A GOOD TEXTURE.
GOOD STUFF, MAN.
THANKS.
NOT BAD. I THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE TALKIN' ABOUT
WHEN YOU'RE TALKIN' TURKEY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
27 YEARS
I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE.
TO WILLIE BIRD'S?
THAT'S RIGHT.
NICE.
YOU'RE QUITE WELCOME.
IN FACT, WILLIE BIRD'S HAS
BEEN HERE SO LONG THAT BY NOW
THE LOCALS DON'T EVEN THINK
THERE'S ANYTHING WEIRD
ABOUT A PLACE
THAT SERVES TURKEY...
THAT'S GREAT.
TURKEY AND TURKEY.
THAT IS A GOOD-LOOKIN' LEG.
AND IT'S STARTIN' TO FEEL
LIKE THIS PLACE
HAS BEEN HERE FOREVER.
SOME OF THIS STUFF,
LIKE, UP HERE...
YEAH, THAT WAS THE OLD,
UH, WHERE THEY HAD THE PRICES
AND EVERYTHING UP THERE.
SO IN 27 YEARS, YOU STILL
NEVER CHANGED ANY OF IT?
MM, NO.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
LOOK UP THERE?
THAT'S THE FIRST TIME I'VE
LOOKED UP THERE IN 27 YEARS.
AFTER ALL, WILLIE KNOWS
WHY THE CROWDS ARE HERE.
MY MOTHER CAN'T MAKE IT
LIKE WILLIE BIRD'S CAN.
AS POPULAR AS THE ENTIRE
TURKEY MENU IS...
ALWAYS HOLD THE DRUMSTICK
BY ITS HANDLE HERE.
HOMEMADE.
WILLIE SAYS YOU STILL
CAN'T BEAT THE BASICS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
(Willie) YOU KNOW, THE BIGGEST
SELL IS THE ROAST TURKEY DINNER.
HANDS DOWN?
THEY COULD EAT--
THEY COULD--
YEAH, THANKSGIVING
DINNER EVERY DAY,
365 DAYS A YEAR.
THIS IS THE REAL McCOY.
CLOSEST TO HOME
I'M GONNA GET.
REALLY?
(Willie) AND THERE WE GO.
MMM. THAT'S TALKIN'
TURKEY RIGHT THERE.
THAT GOOD, HUH?
THAT'S TENDER, MAN.
MM-HMM. MAN, I CAN SEE YA
GETTIN' YOUNGER ALREADY.
I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE PROBABLY
SINCE IT'S BEEN OPEN--
THE SAME MEAL, THE SAME DISH.
JUST DON'T CHANGE THE TURKEY.
THAT AIN'T GONNA HAPPEN.
AFTER ALL, WILLIE'S GOT PLENTY
IN THE PIPELINE,
PLENTY OF RECIPES...
LOOK AT THAT.
AND PLENTY OF FOLKS...
ALL RIGHT.
I'M HUNGRY AND READY TO EAT.
WHO KEEP PACKIN' IN.
DRIVE ALL OVER THE COUNTRY JUST
TO COME BACK HERE TO EAT THIS.
WILLIE KNOWS HOW
TO DO TURKEY.
IF YOU WANT A GOOD DINNER
EVERY SINGLE TIME,
CONSISTENCY,
COME TO WILLIE BIRD'S.
CAN YOU MAKE A TURKEY CALL?
NOT TOO GOOD.
LET ME HEAR IT.
I'VE HEARD 'EM.
(imitates turkey gobble)
LOOK, THEY'RE ALL LEAVIN'.
THEY GOT TIRED OF US.
TOOK TOO LONG.
THE PIED PIPER OF TURKEYS.
UP NEXT, A FLORIDA JOINT
WHERE STUFFING A TURKEY
MEANS A WHOLE NOTHER THING.
THAT IS A FLAVOR FEST
RIGHT THERE.
WHEN YOU'RE THINKIN'
ABOUT TURKEY,
YOU'RE PROBABLY NOT THINKIN'
OF A JOINT LIKE THIS.
THE ALPINE STEAKHOUSE
IN SARASOTA, FLORIDA,
IS MORE OF LIKE A SIRLOIN
AND SAUSAGE KIND OF PLACE,
BUT WAIT TILL YOU SEE WHAT
THEY'RE DOIN' WITH TURKEY.
IT'S GONNA BLOW YOU AWAY.
I LOVE IT,
ALL THE DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING BETTER.
IT'S LIKE THANKSGIVING
JUST ALL THE TIME.
NO, SERIOUSLY, MAN.
THEY TAKE A CHICKEN.
THEY SHOVE IT IN A DUCK,
AND THEY SHOVE THE DUCK
INSIDE THE TURKEY,
AND THEN THEY PUT A BUNCH
OF STUFFING AND STUFF ON IT.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
IT'S CALLED A TURDUCKEN,
JUST ONE OF THE HANDMADE,
HOMEMADE SPECIALTIES
TRANSPLANTED NEW YORKER
MARK REBHAN
AND HIS SON MATT
ARE CRANKING OUT...
NEED SOME FRIES DOWN.
AT THE RESTAURANT
AND BUTCHER SHOP
FIRST OPENED BY MARK'S DAD
32 YEARS AGO.
MY DAD BASICALLY CAME
TO FLORIDA TO RETIRE,
AND THAT DIDN'T
LAST TOO LONG...
YEAH, IT LOOKS LIKE HE REALLY
DID A GOOD JOB OF IT.
AND, UH, WENT BACK
INTO BUSINESS,
AND I CAME DOWN IN '75,
AND HERE I AM.
ABOUT 12 YEARS AGO,
MARK SAYS HE HEARD ABOUT
SOMETHING CALLED A TURDUCKEN.
YOUR DAD COMES HOME ONE DAY
AND SAYS, "GUESS WHAT.
"YOU'RE GONNA START BONIN'
CHICKENS, DUCKS AND TURKEYS,
"MAKIN' ALL THIS STUFF
AND SHOVIN' IT TOGETHER
AND THEN SEWIN' IT UP
LIKE A FOOTBALL."
YEAH.
WHAT'D YOU SAY?
WELL, BASICALLY,
HE PUT ONE ON THE COUNTER,
AND HE STARTED
DOIN' ONE HIMSELF,
AND WE JUST DID IT
SIDE-BY-SIDE.
YOU GUYS LEARNED IT
TOGETHER?
YEAH.
LET ME--LET ME LEARN--
LEARN ME.
WELL, BASICALLY, I MEAN,
YOU HAVE A CHICKEN,
A DUCK AND A TURKEY.
SO WHAT I'M GONNA DO...
SHOW ME.
IS I'M GONNA TAKE THIS CHICKEN
AND CUT IT RIGHT DOWN THE BACK.
I CALL THIS
THE SCISSOR CUT HERE.
YOU WANT TO GET
YOUR KNIFE TIP IN HERE.
THIS IS THE OYSTER MEAT
OF THE CHICKEN, BEST PART.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THE DUCK.
SAME WAY.
I LIKE THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE CULINARY
DISNEY LAND FOR A DUDE LIKE ME.
ALL RIGHT.
BIG TURKEY.
IF I'M DOWN FAR ENOUGH,
THIS IS GONNA PULL RIGHT OUT.
OH!
STOCKPOT.
THAT WAS MONEY, DUDE.
YEAH.
OKAY, CAN I TRY THIS ONE?
SURE. ABSOLUTELY.
BE MY GUEST.
I FEEL A GOOD FINGER
CUTTING COMING IN.
THEN YOU'RE JUST GONNA KINDA
GO DOWN, PULL THE MEAT.
THERE IT IS.
GOOD JOB.
(roars)
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE DUCK
AND THE CHICKEN.
I'M GONNA HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE CAJUN SEASONING.
THROW THE DUCK DOWN,
SAME WITH THE CHICKEN.
CHICKEN GOES ON A LITTLE--
THIS IS THE SUPER-HOT SIDE,
A LITTLE LESS HOT.
RIGHT, RIGHT. OKAY,
NOW WHAT I'M GONNA DO--
PUT SOME OF THEM BLACKENING
SEASONINGS ON THERE.
OH!
(laughs)
I LIKE HOW YOU LET ME
JUMP IN ON THIS PART.
HEY...
NOW TO START PIECING
THIS BAD BOY TOGETHER.
VIRGIN OLIVE OIL HERE.
GET IT INTO THE SEAMS,
THE POCKETS WHERE YOU TOOK
THE THIGH BONES OUT.
A LITTLE BLACKENING
ON THIS GUY.
THEN TAKE SOME OF THIS
CORNBREAD STUFFING HERE.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA GO
TO YOUR SPINACH STUFFING HERE.
AND YOU'RE GONNA PUT
SOME ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
AND YOU GUYS MAKE
THE ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE ALSO?
HERE ON PREMISES.
SOME ROASTED RED BELL PEPPERS.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA TAKE
YOUR DUCK INSIDE THIS TURKEY.
LET ME ASK YOU THIS, BOSS.
WHY ISN'T THE CHICKEN DOWN?
HE'S BIGGER.
WELL, TUR-DUCK-EN.
THAT'S THE TURKEY, THEN
THE DUCK, THEN THE CHICKEN.
GIVE ME THE KNIFE.
YOU'RE NOT DOIN'
AS MUCH NOW.
YOU'RE JUST KINDA
HIDIN' IT IN THERE NOW.
YEAH. NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
TO THE CHICKEN.
I BET YOU HAVE
A LOT OF FRIENDS
COME THANKSGIVING
AND CHRISTMASTIME.
(laughs) YOU'RE JUST
GONNA TAKE IT,
AND YOU'RE GONNA BRING IT UP
AND TURN IT LIKE THIS.
SOMETIMES IT'S BEST TO HAVE
A FRIEND HELP YOU HOLD IT.
I GRAB--
LET ME SEE
IF I CAN FIND SOMEBODY.
WHEN IS YOUR, UH, SPRING
CLOTHING LINE COMING OUT?
'CAUSE YOU'RE REALLY
DOIN' A MACK JOB.
DUDE, YOU MAKE
THAT LOOK SO EASY.
THAT MIGHT BE ONE
OF THE BEST-LOOKING
UNCOOKED FOOD ITEMS
I'VE EVER--
I MEAN,
IT'S JUST BEAUTIFUL.
AND YOU JUST WANT TO KINDA
SET IT UP IN HERE.
NOW HOW LONG DOES
SUPER BIRD TAKE?
THIS SUPER BIRD HERE
IS GONNA TAKE
ABOUT 12 TO 13 HOURS
AT 200 DEGREES.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA. HOW MANY?
12 TO 13 HOURS.
OKAY, SO THAT GOES IN.
SLIDE IT ON IN THERE.
SO YOU JUST CLOSE
THAT OVEN, AND...
(whistles)
IT'S HOT.
(both) ONE, TWO, THREE.
ALL RIGHT.
I FEEL BETTER.
I--HEY, YOU DO?
I'M GONNA CUT IT
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
STEAM COMIN' OFF THAT.
OH, YOU SHOULD SMELL THAT!
HOLY MOLY.
HOW'S THAT LOOK FOR YA?
♪♪
OH, MAN.
IT'S A GOOD COMBINATION.
DEFINITELY NEED THE RICHNESS
OF THE DUCK AND THE FAT,
AND THEN...
YOU KNOW WHAT I PICK UP
IN THERE IS THE ANDOUILLE.
MM-HMM.
AND THE CHICKEN HAS
SUCH A LIGHTER TEXTURE...
MM-HMM.
THAN THE TURKEY.
YEAH.
THAT IS A FLAVOR FEST
RIGHT THERE.
MMM.
GUY, YOU HAVEN'T EVEN
HAD GRAVY ON IT YET.
WHY WOULD YOU COVER THAT
WITH ANYTHING?
IT TASTES--SERIOUSLY.
THAT'S LIKE SOMEONE SHOT OFF
ALL THE FIREWORKS
AT THE SAME TIME.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
EVERYBODY GETS A TASTE.
HAVE YOU HAD IT BEFORE?
NEVER. I'M A ROOKIE.
AND IF TURDUCKEN'S NOT ENOUGH,
WE'RE STARTING OFF THE MEAL
WITH A TRUE AMERICAN CLASSIC.
THAT'S MONEY.
HERE AT THE ALPINE STEAKHOUSE
IN SARASOTA, FLORIDA...
HOLY MOLY.
THEIR OFF-THE-HOOK TURDUCKEN IS
KNOCKIN' FOLKS OUT OF THE COOP.
SO GOOD.
IT'S VERY, VERY
TENDER AND MOIST.
AND THE TURDUCKEN IS JUST ONE
OF THE SPECIALTIES HERE...
YOU GOT IT.
WHERE THEY MAKE THEIR OWN
SAUSAGE, CUT THEIR OWN STEAKS
AND CRANK OUT CLASSIC
OYSTERS ROCKEFELLER
TO GET YOU STARTED...
OYSTERS ROCK ARE UP.
WHILE THAT TURDUCKEN'S
STILL IN THE OVEN.
OYSTERS. SEASONINGS.
DUN-DUN-DAH. SPINACH.
OKAY, TEACH.
OKAY. BUTTER'S BETTER.
GONNA SAUTé IT
IN THE FRYING PAN.
CUP AND A HALF,
2 CUPS OF CELERY.
CHOPPED GREEN ONIONS.
GONNA TAKE SOME PARSLEY.
GONNA ADD MY CHOPPED...
I'LL TAKE YOUR BLADE.
OH, THANK YOU.
SAME TEAM.
SPICES--
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT,
WHITE PEPPER, CAYENNE.
CAYENNE?
HOW HOT DO YOU WANT IT?
OH, NO. I WANT TO BE ABLE
TO TASTE THE OYSTER--NOT.
GARLIC GOES IN NOW?
YEAH.
ONE, TWO...
I PUT IT ALL IN.
OKAY. I HAVE A RESTAURANT
CALLED JOHNNY GARLIC'S.
I CAN DEAL WITH IT.
BUT WHILE YOU STIR, I'LL ADD
THESE LITTLE SEASONINGS IN HERE.
I ALREADY LIKE
WHERE THIS IS GOIN'.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE NEXT, GUY?
YOU WANT
THE "PER-NOD," "PER-NO,"
OR WOULD YOU LIKE
THE SPINACH?
THE "PER-NEED,"
"PER-NADE."
I LIKE IT. WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK ABOUT A CUP.
THERE WE GO.
OYSTERS FLAMBé.
OH, YOU CAN DEFINITELY
PICK UP THE NOSE WITH THAT.
SPINACH.
I LIKE THAT YOU'RE USIN'
THE FRESH SPINACH
VERSUS USIN'
THE FROZEN SPINACH.
OYSTER TIME.
I'VE BEEN THROUGH SHANKIN'
MYSELF ENOUGH TIMES
THAT YOU DO IT NICE AND SLOW,
TAKE YOUR TIME,
LOOSEN IT UP,
AND THERE WE GO.
OYSTERS ARE READY
TO GET STUFFED,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
FILL THESE UP HERE.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
YOU WANT ME TO DUST 'EM?
DUST 'EM, AND THEN
THEY'RE GOIN' IN THE OVEN.
HOW MUCH YOU WANT,
LIKE THAT?
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
READY FOR LUNCH.
THIS IS HOW WE SERVE IT?
THAT'S HOW WE SERVE IT.
THAT'S A BOUNTY.
♪♪
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF OYSTERS ROCKEFELLER,
BUT I THINK THAT
THAT SPINACH COMBO,
AND YOU--YOU REALLY JACK UP
THE PERNOD ON THAT.
YOU REALLY GOT AN ANISE
FLAVOR IN THERE.
AND THE FENNEL,
I THINK, HELPS.
YEAH.
THAT IS GOOD EATS.
DUDE, THAT'S MONEY.
SEEMS MARK AND MATT
JUST HAVE A WAY
WITH STUFFING THINGS
FULL OF FLAVOR...
LOOK AT THIS THING.
THERE YOU GO.
FIRST COURSE OR MAIN MEAL.
ALL RIGHT.
SET THESE GUYS LOOSE, AND YOU
REALLY ARE TALKIN' TURKEY.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD, MAN.
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
I TELL YA, THIS IS REALLY--
THIS HAS FULFILLED A DREAM.
GOOD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(laughing)
DID YOU SEE THAT?
ALL THE--
(man) HOW DOES
THAT GO AGAIN?
YES.