HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
CHEERS.
BON APPéTIT.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THAT IS FANTASTIC, MAN.
PLACES...
I LOVE THIS LITTLE PLACE.
AND PLATES...
MMM.
THAT ARE OFF THE HOOK.
I THINK YOUR EYEBALLS
ARE SWEATIN'.
IN KANSAS CITY...
CHECK YOUR ATTITUDE
AT THE DOOR.
THE PLACE TO GO
FOR TATER TOT PIZZA...
THIS IS LIKE BEING
IN GRADE SCHOOL AGAIN.
CHEESESTEAKS LIKE
THEY MAKE 'EM IN PHILLY...
THAT'S GOOD EATS
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
AND FRESH
WELDED SCULPTURE
THEY'RE MAKIN' OUT BACK.
THAT'S CRAZY.
A CALIFORNIA JOINT
BY THE WATER...
I WONDERED WHERE I HAD
PARKED MY FOUR BOATS.
WHERE THEY'RE LININ' UP...
OH, IT'S SO WORTH IT.
FOR SOMETHIN' CALLED
SCHULTZIE'S MESS.
I'LL DOWN THAT
IN TWO MINUTES.
NO.
YEAH.
IN MICHIGAN, A PLACE CALLED
THE FLY TRAP WHERE THIS...
WOW, IT'S GOT GREAT SPICE.
IS DINER COOKIN'.
THIS IS TOO GORGEOUS
TO EAT IN THE KITCHEN.
AND OFF THE HOOK IN CHICAGO...
IT'S AWESOME.
THE BARBECUE COMES TO YOU.
(Guy) I THINK YOU
CAN STAND UP
NEXT TO SOME
OF THE BIG BOYS.
THAT'S GOOD BARBECUE.
WHY, THANK YOU.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN I SAY, "KANSAS CITY,"
YOU'RE PROBABLY THINKIN'
STEAK OR BARBECUE,
BUT NOT ON THIS TRIP.
TODAY I'M THINKIN'
SOMETHING ELSE,
LIKE AN OLD AUTO-PARTS-STORE-
TURNED-RESTAURANT
RUN BY A TRANSPLANTED,
EAST-COASTER SCULPTOR
WHERE THE PLACE AND THE FOOD
ARE BOTH OFF THE HOOK--
A PLACE LIKE GRINDERS.
CHECK YOUR ATTITUDE AT
THE DOOR, IS WHAT WE SAY.
HERE YOU GO.
THAT'S WINGS!
HOLDIN' DOWN.
HIS NAME IS STRETCH.
I'M A VERY BIG MAN.
HE OWNS THE PLACE.
I'M THE GUY THAT COLORS
OUTSIDE THE LINES.
BRITISH ARMY HELMETS,
CIRCA 1943.
HE'S DIFFERENT.
(growling)
AND HE'S GOT
AN OFF-THE-HOOK WAY
OF DOING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
YOU DID THAT BACKWARDS.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S HOWEVER
I WANT TO DO IT.
THE BEER TOWER.
IT'S A BREATHING TANK
FOR OXYGEN, YEAH.
STRETCHIFIED.
YEAH, WELL, IT'S STRETCH--
THE FOOD IS STRETCH-A-LICIOUS.
THERE YOU GO.
THE PIZZA
IS JUST MY FAVORITE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
WITH ALL KINDS
OF HOMEMADE KINDS...
I LOVE THIS PIE.
FROM CLASSIC TO TATER TOT...
MAN, THIS IS LIKE BEING
IN GRADE SCHOOL AGAIN.
CHEESESTEAKS STRETCH INSISTS
ARE BETTER THAN THE ONES
HE GREW UP WITH...
I'M FROM PHILLY AREA.
I THINK I CAN MAKE A CHEESESTEAK
WHEREVER I GO IN THE WORLD.
HOT WINGS THAT'LL PUT YOU DOWN
FOR THE COUNT...
YOUR EYEBALLS
ARE SWEATIN'.
IN A HUNDRED-YEAR-OLD BUILDING
WITH FOOD IN THE FRONT...
LOVE IT.
AND MONSTER METAL SCULPTURES
IN THE BACK.
IT'S ABOUT 24 FEET TALL.
WEIGHS ABOUT 9,000 POUNDS.
THAT'S CRAZY.
NO CRAZIER
THAN STRETCH DECIDING
IT MAKES PERFECT SENSE
FOR A SCULPTOR
TO OPEN A RESTAURANT.
(Stretch) ART LIKE FOOD
LIKE MUSIC
CROSSES ALL CULTURAL
BOUNDARIES.
IT DOES.
AND THIS PLACE IS JUST
ALL THAT PUT TOGETHER,
JUST MISHED AND MASHED.
AND TOSSED AND BAKED...
(Stretch) THAT'S OUR PIE
RIGHT THERE.
STARTING ENTIRELY
FROM SCRATCH.
YOU JUST WORK YOUR
FINGERS INTO IT,
GET ALL THEM
AIR BUBBLES OUT.
BUT I GOTTA TELL YA,
HE'S PUTTING MORE TIME
INTO ONE SKIN THAN I'VE
SEEN OTHER PEOPLE
PUT INTO THE WHOLE PIZZA.
LET ME SEE THIS THING.
I CAN ALMOST
SEE THROUGH IT.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT
TO HAVE THIS.
I SAY WE MAKE OUR FAMOUS
BENGAL TIGER.
WHY'D YOU CALL IT
BENGAL TIGER?
YOU KNOW, WE GOT
THIS CHICKEN IN THERE,
AND THE TANDOORI SAUCE.
IT'S GOT CURRY IN IT
AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
LITTLE PESTO GOES DOWN.
THAT'S THE LITTLE PESTO.
WE SPRINKLE
ON OUR TANDOORI CHICKEN.
CURRY--
LITTLE CURRY ON THERE.
NOW HOW DOES THIS
GO OVER HERE
IN, UH, IN THE HEART
OF THE BEEF LAND?
THIS IS ONE OF OUR FAVORITE
PIZZAS. PEOPLE LOVE IT.
IT'S EVEN GOT A LITTLE CRAB
ON IT AND HEARTS OF PALM.
'CAUSE I OFTEN,
WHEN I'M THINKIN' PIZZA,
I'M THINKIN' HEARTS OF PALM.
AND WE SPRINKLE A LITTLE
OF OUR CHEESE ON TOP,
AND THAT'S
ABOUT IT RIGHT THERE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THAT IS GORGEOUS.
SO CILANTRO.
CILANTRO.
JUST DRIP IT IN THERE
A LITTLE BIT LIKE THAT.
BENGAL TIGER.
RAWR!
WOW.
THAT'S LIKE AN ALL-CALYPSO-
JAZZ-BAND-FESTIVAL,
FUNKALICIOUS
ROCK CONCERT.
I HEAR IT'S GOOD.
DELICIOUS--
YOU GET, LIKE, THESE GEMS,
LITTLE HEARTS OF PALM,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE CHICKEN,
SOME CRAB.
IT'S THE YIN
AND THE YANG OF PIZZA.
IT REALLY WORKS.
STRETCH'LL MAKE
ANYTHING WORK.
(woman) I LOVE IT,
BECAUSE YOU CAN KIND OF
SPECIALTY ORDER IT.
LIKE, YOU GET YOUR OWN SLICE
AND DECIDE WHAT'S ON IT.
IN ANY COMBINATION...
(Stretch) SO WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME SALMON ON HERE NOW.
LIKE SMOKED SALMON
AND CREAM CHEESE ON PESTO.
WOW!
THAT'S NO JOKE.
THERE'S ONE WITH SPINACH,
PEPPERS, ARTICHOKES,
OLIVES AND ALMONDS--
FOUR KINDS TOGETHER
WITH THE PEPPERONI
NEXT TO THE PINEAPPLE.
AND THIS BABY
THAT MAKES YOU WONDER
WHY NO ONE EVER DID IT
BEFORE...
THE CHILI AND THE ONIONS--
FRESH-CUT ONIONS--
THE SURPRISE
IS THE TATER TOT.
SO THIS PIE ACTUALLY HAS A HOLE
OUT OF THE CENTER OF IT,
AND WE PUT TATER TOTS
IN THE MIDDLE.
WE PUT CHILI ON TOP OF IT,
CHEEZ WHIZ ON TOP OF THAT,
AND THEN WE PUT SOME
GREEN ONIONS ON TOP OF THAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
TASTY CHILI.
MMM, AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
NOTHIN' GOES BETTER
THAN A TOT.
FOOD IS ALWAYS JUST GREAT.
AND WHILE STRETCH STARTED THIS
AS AN ARTIST, NOT A CHEF...
IT'S JUST LIKE YOUR OWN
LITTLE MINI ART GALLERY.
AND IT CHANGES.
PEOPLE BRING US STUFF.
AND THAT'S WHAT
I LIKE ABOUT IT.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE FOOD,
HE GOT REAL SERIOUS
REAL QUICK.
(Guy) LOOK AT THAT.
(Stretch) I HAD A FRIEND
WHO WENT TO NEW YORK
AT THE CULINARY
INSTITUTE UP THERE.
HE CAME BACK AND HELPED ME
OPEN A RESTAURANT,
SO A LOT OF THE RECIPES ARE
DERIVED FROM HIS, YOU KNOW...
NICE, OKAY.
PARTICIPATION.
SO THAT'S WHY
YOU'VE REALLY GOT
SOME TRUE CULINARY
FOUNDATION.
YEAH.
BUT THERE'S ALSO THE STUFF THAT
STRETCH BROUGHT TO THE PARTY.
I USED TO LIVE
IN PHILADELPHIA,
AND THIS IS THE FIRST PLACE
THAT'S EXACTLY THE SAME
AS I REMEMBER
FROM BACK HOME.
THE SECRET IS DEFINITELY
SEASONING THE GRILL BEFOREHAND.
WE'VE THROWN BACON
ON THERE ALL DAY LONG
AND CHEESESTEAK,
SO IT'S GONNA BE FINE.
NICE, LEAN ROAST BEEF
WE USE.
CHOP IT UP.
THE OTHER SECRET
IS SLICIN' THE BUN.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
PEPPERS FIRST,
THEN PUT A LITTLE
ONIONS ON THERE.
MIX IT IN THERE.
PUT MY CHEEZ WHIZ ON HERE.
THAT'S A PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
IN KANSAS CITY.
CHEERS.
BON APPéTIT.
THAT'S TASTY.
THAT'S GOOD EATS
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
AS SOON AS YOU THINK
YOU GOT IT PEGGED,
GRINDERS THROWS YOU
ANOTHER CURVE BALL.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
YOU GOT HERE IS GEORGE.
I'M THE HUNGARIAN DELIGHT
ON MONDAYS.
THE HUNGARIAN DELIGHT?
YES.
DO YOU OFFICIALLY
WORK HERE?
OR IS THIS KIND OF JUST,
LIKE, COMMUNITY SERVICE?
ITS IS PRO BONO.
GEORGE IS STRETCH'S
LONG-TIME FRIEND,
A RETIRED RESTAURATEUR
WHO COMES IN ONCE A WEEK
TO DO HUNGARIAN SPECIALTIES
LIKE CHICKEN PAPRIKASH.
EXCELLENT.
(Guy) SO YOU'VE KNOWN
TO COME HERE FOR THIS.
ABSOLUTELY. YEAH.
GOT SOME ONIONS GOIN'?
RIGHT.
RED CHILI FLAKE?
THE HUNGARIAN PAPRIKA?
YES.
NOW YOU SEE HOW VERY CAREFULLY
I MEASURE HERE.
YEAH. OH, GOOD.
OH, REAL TECHNICAL.
TOMATO JUICE.
PUT THE CHICKEN IN?
THANK YOU FOR HELPING!
AND HOW LONG DOES THAT GO?
ABOUT AN HOUR.
JUST BEFORE IT'S DONE,
GEORGE TOSSES IN SOME MUSHROOMS
AND THEN...
I ALWAYS PUT
PARMESAN CHEESE ON IT.
WILL THIS DO?
THAT IS FANTASTIC, MAN.
IT'S JUST SUCH
A GREAT, BIG FLAVOR.
NO WONDER EVERYBODY
COMES ON MONDAYS.
CHEERS.
GRINDERS IS JUST AN ARTISTIC,
UNUSUAL, FRIENDLY PLACE
WHERE YOU CAN GET
A REALLY GREAT PIECE OF PIZZA.
VERY ECLECTIC ATMOSPHERE.
WE CAME FROM THE OTHER SIDE, NOT
FROM THE CULINARY BACKGROUND.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
RIGHT AND WHAT'S WRONG,
BUT WE KNOW WHAT WE LIKE,
AND WE TRY AND PUT IT
INTO--INTO ACTION IN A PLACE
THAT WE ALL WANT TO GO
AND HANG OUT.
(scattered applause)
THEY LOVE YOU HERE.
LOVE THAT, BUDDY!
THAT'S GOOD!
COMIN' UP...
SPICY. REGULAR.
WE'RE HEADIN' WEST
TO LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA...
BEAUTIFUL SCENERY,
GREAT FOOD.
FOR AN OFF-THE-HOOK SPECIALTY
CALLED SCHULTZIE'S MESS...
I'LL DOWN THAT
IN TWO MINUTES.
NO.
YEAH.
AND ONE OF MY FAVORITE
WEEKEND HANGOUTS.
MMM, THAT'S FABULOUS.
I'M CRUISIN' IN--WELL, ACTUALLY,
LET ME CORRECT MYSELF.
I'M BOATING IN TO A PLACE
CALLED SCHOONER OR LATER.
NOW A SCHOONER COULD BE
A SAILING VESSEL,
OR IT COULD BE A LARGE,
ICE-COLD CHALICE
OF FERMENTED HOPS,
BUT IN MY WORLD,
SCHOONER OR LATER
IS AN OFF-THE-HOOK EATERY
IN LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA.
BEAUTIFUL SCENERY,
GREAT FOOD.
GETTING CRAZY EVERYWHERE.
ONION RINGS?
IT'S A BIG EXPERIENCE...
I WONDERED WHERE
I HAD PARKED MY FOUR BOATS.
IT'S WONDERFUL. SIT OUTSIDE.
SIT BY THE BOATS.
WITH BIG FOOD.
YOU GOT, LIKE, SIX OR SEVEN
FRIENDS THAT ARE COMIN'?
I'LL DOWN THAT
IN TWO MINUTES.
NO.
YEAH.
THERE YOU GO.
A BIG WEEKEND HANGOUT...
THE SUNDAY FUN DAY--WE GET TO
HANG OUT WITH ALL OUR FRIENDS.
WITH A BIG LINE OF FANS...
(man) Sarah, party of two?
WHO INSIST IT'S
WORTH THE WAIT.
WE'RE GONNA WAIT
FOR AN HOUR.
TWO HOURS.
OH, IT'S SO WORTH IT.
MMM, IT'S FABULOUS.
AN AVOCADO,
SOME HOLLANDAISE SAUCE.
AWESOME.
AND AN AWESOME TRADITION.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
I WAS COMING IN HERE
AND EATING WITH MY FATHER.
DENNY LUND AND HIS SISTER
DENISE GREW UP COMING HERE,
THEN BOUGHT THE PLACE
FROM THE ORIGINAL OWNER,
A GUY NAMED SCHULTZIE,
WHOSE SIGNATURE ITEM
IS STILL ON THE MENU.
AND THAT IS
THE SCHULTZIE'S MESS.
WE INHERITED IT FROM HIM.
I ORDERED THE MESS.
EVERYTHING YOU WANT IN BREAKFAST
THROWN ON A PLATE
JUST READY TO ROLL.
HEAD CHEF TONY GALOPé HAS BEEN
MAKING THE MESS FOR 20 YEARS.
SO HOW MANY DO YOU THINK
IS THE MOST YOU'VE SERVED
IN ONE DAY?
50, 60 SOMETIMES.
IN ONE DAY.
(whistles)
START WITH POTATOES.
THIS IS THE MIX
OF BELL PEPPER,
HAM AND ONION.
THEN WE PUT TWO EGGS,
MIX THOSE TOGETHER.
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF CRUST ON IT.
THEN I PUT CHEDDAR
CHEESE ON THE TOP.
COVER IT.
THAT STEAMS IT A LITTLE BIT...
YES.
AND MELTS THE CHEESE?
YEAH, AND MELTS
THE CHEESE.
GOT IT. BEAUTIFUL.
COUPLE PIECES OF TOAST.
COUPLE OF TOAST.
AND THAT'S IT.
MMM. OH, THAT IS
GOOD STUFF.
SEE, I LIKE THIS PART.
OH, CRUNCHY PART.
THE ONIONS AND THE PEPPERS
STILL HAVE CRUNCH.
YEAH, A LITTLE.
THEY'RE COOKED
AND THEY'RE HOT
AND THEY'RE WARM, BUT THEY STILL
GOT A LITTLE CRUNCH IN 'EM.
THAT'S AS GOOD
AS THEY COME.
I SEE WHY THEY CALL
IT THE MESS.
I COULD EAT HERS
AND MINE TOGETHER.
IT'S A MESS, BUT IT'S GOOD.
AND THEY'RE MAKIN'
MORE THAN A MESS HERE.
EGGS BENEDICT--
THE BEST EVER.
THE CRAB
OMELET'S FABULOUS.
THE CRAB OMELET?
THE ITALIAN OMELET
WITH A MARINARA SAUCE,
THE SAUSAGE--
REALLY GOOD.
THEY LOVE HIS SHOW.
(man) YOU SEE THEM PUT AN OMELET
ON THE PLATE OVER THERE.
IT JUST--IT FOLDS OVER
AND IT'S STEAMY,
AND IT'S FILLED WITH ALL SORTS
OF DIFFERENT, GOOD THINGS.
LORI, PARTY OF FOUR.
AND IT'S ALL WORTH
TRAVELIN' FOR.
YOU SHOULD KNOW, WE DROVE
ALL THE WAY FROM KANSAS
TO COME TO SCHOONERS.
(Guy) ALL THE WAY
FROM KANSAS?
YEAH.
AND I COME FROM OREGON,
AND WHEN I COME DOWN HERE,
I ALWAYS COME
TO SCHOONER OR LATER.
I'M FROM GRAND RAPIDS,
MICHIGAN.
FROM BOYNTON BEACH,
FLORIDA.
LAKE WORTH, FLORIDA.
AND YOU'RE FROM...
I'M THE LOCAL.
THE ITALIAN OMELET?
CRAB OMELET?
AND THE MESS.
BETWEEN THE VISITORS
AND THE REGULARS...
AN ORDER OF...
THEY CAN SERVE A THOUSAND
PEOPLE ON AN AVERAGE SUNDAY...
(Denny) Snow, party of five?
Snow?
AND A WHOLE LOT OF THEM
ARE GOIN' FOR THIS.
I ORDERED A BELGIAN WAFFLE
WITH BANANAS,
STRAWBERRIES AND BLUEBERRIES.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
(Tony) WE JUST KEEP GOING
AND GOING AND GOING.
SOMETIMES WE DON'T--
YOU'RE LIKE
THE ENERGIZER WAFFLE BUNNY.
WHEN THE TIMER SAYS,
"RING!"
AND THEN IT'S DONE.
WHAT DOES
THE TIMER DO?
"RING!"
HOW?
DOES IT GO "RING"?
A WATCHED WAFFLE--
(timer rings)
THERE YOU GO.
JUST ONE DING.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S GOT BANANA, STRAWBERRY
AND BLUEBERRIES.
WHIPPED CREAM
ON THE TOP.
MMM, THAT'S
A GREAT WAFFLE.
NICE FRESH FRUIT,
BLUEBERRY AND EVERYTHING.
MM-HMM.
WHAT DID YOU THINK
OF THE, UH, WAFFLE?
VERY GOOD. VERY GOOD.
VERY GOOD?
BIG? BIG WAFFLE?
YEAH.
IT'S ALL BIG, AND MORE
THAN THAT, IT'S REAL.
FRESH-COOKED--WHAT YOU WANT
THE WAY YOU WANT IT.
(Guy) SPINACH AND SOMETHING?
EGG WHITES.
EVEN AS BUSY
AS SCHOONER OR LATER IS,
THEY SEEM LIKE THEY DO
THE EGG WHITES,
THEY DO THE EGG WHITE
OMELETS.
ALWAYS, AND THEY
HAVE GREAT SPINACH.
AND FOR THEIR
TURKEY CLUB MELT...
JUST ORDERED ONE OF
THOSE TO GO.
I'M ACTUALLY GONNA TAKE
THAT WITH ME TO WORK.
THEY'RE EVEN ROASTING
FRESH TURKEYS.
WE GONNA SLICE IT
ON THE SLICER.
THAT'S GOOD TURKEY.
STACKIN' 'EM HIGH WITH HAM,
TURKEY, CHEESE,
AND TOMATO.
PUT IT TOGETHER.
ONE, TWO...
WE CUT IT
FOUR TIMES.
I JUST GOTTA
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THIS IS GOOD.
FRESH TURKEY.
MM!
THIS TURKEY MAKES
ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
LOOK AT THAT--
ALL THE CHEESE.
YOU DON'T NEED ANY MUSTARD OR
MAYONNAISE ON THAT AT ALL.
GOOD JOB, MAN. THAT TURKEY
IS THE KEY RIGHT THERE.
CLUB SANDWICH.
YOU KNOW THAT THEY
ROAST THAT TURKEY?
WELL, SOMETIMES WE HAVE
SCHOONERS, TOO,
INSTEAD OF--
I WAS WONDERIN'
WHERE THEY WERE.
I SEE DECAF AND REGULAR.
I MEAN, THE--
HAVE THESE REMOVED
IMMEDIATELY.
(woman) AND I NEED
ANOTHER SCHOONER.
AFTER ALL, IT IS
"SCHOONER" OR LATER.
IT'S A CHALICE
OF FERMENTED HOPS.
SCHOONER OR LATER.
EVERY SUNDAY.
DON'T MISS IT.
COME DOWN TO THE SHORE,
HAVE A LITTLE MESS.
IT KINDA CURES EVERYTHING.
(man) I LOVE
THIS LITTLE PLACE.
IF I WON
THE LOTTERY TOMORROW,
I WOULDN'T CHANGE
A THING ABOUT THIS.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
IT'S A PIECE OF US,
AND WE TRULY ENJOY IT.
IT'S NOT JUST PRETENDING.
IT'S ALL ABOUT ATMOSPHERE.
VERY FUN.
(Denny) BUT I THINK WE'VE
JUST KIND OF OVER TIME
BECOME AN INSTITUTION.
(Denise) THEY JUST COME
HERE FOR THE DAY.
THEY DON'T MAKE ANY
OTHER PLANS. THEY SAY,
"WHAT ARE WE DOIN' TODAY?"
"WE'RE GOIN' TO SCHOONER."
AND THAT'S IT.
(girls) THIS IS BANANAS
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
HEY, BANANA!
UP NEXT, WE'RE
OFF THE HOOK IN MICHIGAN
AT A DINER WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
EVERYTHING THEIR WAY.
IT MAY BE THE ONLY TIME
YOU'RE GONNA SEE TOFU
WHEN WE DO
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I GREW UP IN THE GREAT TOWN
OF FERNDALE, CALIFORNIA,
WHICH IS EXACTLY
2,543 MILES AWAY
FROM THIS TOWN,
FERNDALE, MICHIGAN,
WHICH IS HOME TO THIS PLACE,
THE FLY TRAP.
IT CALLS ITSELF A FINER DINER,
AND THEIR APPROACH TO DINER FOOD
IS OFF THE HOOK.
RISOTTO CAKES STUFFED
WITH MOZZARELLA.
I'VE GOT THE FRIED RICE DISH.
WOW, IT'S GOT GREAT SPICE.
AN ENSALADA de BASURA.
IT'S DIFFERENT. IT'S FUN.
IT'S COOL.
AND IT'S INEXPENSIVE.
MAY BE THE ONLY TIME
YOU'RE GONNA SEE TOFU
WHEN WE DO
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THE RED CHILI
SALMON BURGER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TELL ME THAT'S NOT
A FESTIVAL OF FLAVOR.
RESTAURANT VETS
GAVIN McMILLIAN...
ORDER UP!
KARA McCLANAGHAN AND HER
UNSUSPECTING BROTHER SHAWN...
I GOT SUCKERED IN.
THEY NEEDED A DISHWASHER
TO GET STARTED.
HAVE TAKEN THE IDEA
OF A CLASSIC DINER
AND DOIN' IT THEIR WAY.
GOURMET BREAKFAST,
8 BUCKS.
NOT BAD.
JUST KINDA MADE IT INTO OUR
LITTLE FUNKY PLACE.
WAS IT A FLY TRAP?
IT REALLY WAS.
WE FIRST GOT IN THERE,
WE HAD TO TEAR EVERYTHING OUT.
WE'RE NOT REAL HANDY, BUT WE
MANAGED TO SWING A HAMMER
AND, UH, THREW IT TOGETHER.
THREW TOGETHER
AN OFF-THE-HOOK MENU, TOO.
CHOPSTICKS?
HEAVY ON ASIAN DISHES,
WHICH GAVIN'S LOVED
SINCE HIS COLLEGE DAYS WITH HIS
JAPANESE-AMERICAN ROOMMATE.
ORDER UP.
END UP GOIN' OVER
TO HIS MOM'S HOUSE
AND--AND GET FREE FOOD,
BASICALLY.
SO ATE A LOT OF JAPANESE FOOD,
AND THAT KIND OF PIQUED
MY INTEREST IN IT.
THESE DAYS, GAVIN'S COOKIN'
ALL KINDS OF ASIAN CUISINE,
FROM TOFU FRIED RICE
WITH ROASTED MUSHROOMS,
PEPPERS AND EGGPLANT...
GOSH, THAT'S TASTY.
SEE YA LATER.
ALL RIGHT.
TO THAI-STYLE
SPICY PEANUT CHICKEN
TO A VIETNAMESE FAVORITE.
PHO BOWL.
EXACTLY.
PHO--"P-H,"
LIKE "P-H" PHAT.
"P-H"--EXACTLY, LIKE PHAT.
IT IS A PHAT DISH.
WE DO BASICALLY A MIREPOIX
OF CARROTS, CELERY AND ONION.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA
THROW SOME MUSHROOMS IN HERE.
GINGER--I JUST LEAVE
THE SKINS ON. I DON'T PEEL IT.
'CAUSE YOU'RE
JUST MAKIN' A STOCK.
EXACTLY.
YELLOW LEMONGRASS.
BASICALLY, IT'S GONNA PULL
THE OILS OUT OF THE LEMONGRASS.
PUT A LITTLE OIL ON THIS.
GONNA ROAST 'EM UP IN THE OVEN
ABOUT A HALF-HOUR.
300?
YEP.
MAN, THE AROMA COMIN'
OFF OF THAT--
WE JUST ADD
A LITTLE WATER.
GONNA PUT SOME FRESH BASIL IN,
A LITTLE FRESH CILANTRO.
YOU'RE A MAD MAN.
I GET CRAZY.
THREE JALAPEÑOS?
EXACTLY THREE.
SOMETIMES FOUR.
AND ONCE IT WAS ONE.
SIMMER?
YEAH, WE JUST WANT
TO BRING OUT THE FLAVORS.
NOW ONLY A GALLON OF WATER.
TRY TO MAKE IT
AS RICH AS POSSIBLE.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT JUST SMELLS FANTASTIC.
SEAR SOME TOFU.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR BROTH--
RED BELL PEPPER,
CARROTS, EGGPLANTS.
THEN OUR SNAPS.
BASIL, SOME SPINACH.
GET THE NOODLES ON THE BOTTOM.
AND THEN I COME UP WITH
A THREE ON TOP SHOT.
MAGICAL SALAD WIZARD MIX.
RIGHT ON TOP.
OH-HO! THIS IS TOO GORGEOUS
TO EAT IN THE KITCHEN.
MMM, I REALLY LIKE--THE BASIL
COMES OUT RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
BUT IT'S THE DEPTH OF
THE FLAVOR, I THINK,
THAT MAKES SUCH
A BIG DIFFERENCE HERE.
THIS RANKS UP WITH SOME OF
THE BEST BOWLS I'VE HAD.
I APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
EVEN THE LESS EXOTIC DISHES
HERE GET A FLY TRAP SPIN.
(Gavin) OVER-MEDIUM.
YOU'VE GOT BEETS
IN THE CORN BEEF HASH
AND GINGERBREAD WAFFLES
WITH HOMEMADE SYRUP,
FRESH APPLES
AND MICHIGAN CHERRIES.
AH, THAT'S TASTY.
I'VE READ IT TO MY KIDS.
I HAD TO COME OUT
AND SEE GREEN EGGS AND HAM.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
POBLANO PESTO, JACK CHEESE,
AND THEY MAKE
THEIR OWN HOT SAUCE.
THEY'VE GOT GREEN BURGERS, TOO,
MADE WITH SPINACH AND FETA,
AND A HOMEMADE SALMON BURGER.
(Gavin) WE'RE GONNA DO
A ROUGH CHOP ON 'EM.
(Guy) NOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA THROW A LITTLE
SAMBAL OELEK IN THERE.
EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
AN ASIAN RED CHILI PASTE
ADDS A LITTLE HEAT.
YOU LOVE WORKIN'
WITH SAMBAL, DON'T YOU?
I DO.
AND AGAIN, THE PRECISE
MEASURING TECHNIQUES.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS EXACT.
OH, WAIT, NONE
OF 'EM ARE.
A LITTLE SOY
AND BLACK SESAME SEEDS.
AND WE PULSE IT.
NOW NO BINDER?
NOPE, IT'LL STICK.
AND THEN TOGETHER,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A SALMON BURGER.
THAT'S A BIG BURGER.
THERE WE GO.
DID YOU SEE THE LITTLE
KICK-OVER ON THE PAN?
I LIKE IT.
IT WAS A NICE STYLE.
ON THE TOP OF OUR BUN,
WE'RE GONNA THROW
A LITTLE LIME AIOLI.
AIOLI MEANING?
WELL, IT'S BASICALLY--
IT'S MY EXCUSE TO PUT
GARLIC IN SOMETHING.
BUT IT'S BASICALLY
A FRENCH MAYONNAISE.
AND FOR CRUNCH, THROW
A FEW CUCUMBERS ON THERE.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
BURGER RIGHT THERE.
MMM, THAT'S
A TASTY SALMON BURGER.
YOU KNOW WHAT I
REALLY LIKE IN THERE?
THE SESAME SEEDS.
I THINK IT'S DELICIOUS.
I THINK IT'S MY
FAVORITE DISH HERE.
REALLY.
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
THAT IS $8.95.
FOR $8.95, DUDE--
I COULD EASILY SEE
THAT BEIN' 12 BUCKS.
I APPRECIATE IT.
I WISH EVERYONE
ELSE COULD.
GOOD PRICES, GOOD FOOD...
CHEAPSTEAK SANDWICH--
MY KIND OF SANDWICH.
WHAT A DINER'S MEANT TO BE.
THE FOOD IS PHENOMENAL.
THE MENU IS THOUGHTFUL
AND IMAGINATIVE.
IT'S COZY. IT'S HOMEY.
IT'S CREATIVE.
IT'S A NICE LITTLE
MOM-AND-POP RESTAURANT
THAT ALWAYS SERVES REALLY
UNIQUE DIFFERENT FOOD
THAT YOU'RE NOT GONNA
FIND ANYWHERE ELSE.
ORGANIC BROWN RICE.
IT IS.
HOW VERY FERNDALE OF YOU.
I GROW IT IN MY BACKYARD.
YOU GROW RICE
IN YOUR BACKYARD--
I WOK.
NO, I WOK IT.
GOOD.
THAT WAS THE BEST
OF THE DAY!
COMIN' UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' FOR CHICAGO...
LOOK AT THE LINE
YOU GOT GOIN'.
WHERE THE PULLED PORK...
(Guy) MMM, GOOD!
IS PULLIN' UP IN AN R.V.
BRINGIN' PORK TO THE PEOPLE.
THAT'S CRAZY TASTY RIGHT THERE.
HERE I AM ON THE NORTHWEST SIDE
OF CHICAGO,
WHEN A QUESTION COMES TO MIND
ABOUT BARBECUE.
IS IT A BARBECUE DRIVE-IN,
OR DID THE BARBECUE
DRIVE IN?
WELCOME TO THE PIG RIG.
WE NEED TWO SANDWICHES.
(woman) OKAY, TWO SANDWICHES
COMIN' UP.
I'VE BEEN HEARIN' ABOUT IT
ALL SUMMER LONG.
LOOK AT THE LINE
YOU GOT GOIN'.
MMM, GOOD!
FROM FARMERS' MARKETS
TO ANY OUTDOOR EVENT,
GRACE DELCANO'S ON A MISSION.
SUE, I NEED A SANDWICH, PLEASE.
BRINGIN' PORK
TO THE PEOPLE.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I COULD HAVE BARBECUE FOR
BREAKFAST, LUNCH AND DINNER.
THERE USED TO BE
OTHER STUFF IN THIS.
YOU TORE IT ALL OUT?
YEAH, RIPPED IT ALL OUT
AND THEN REBUILT
THIS THING.
SO SHE COULD ROLL UP
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE...
THERE YOU GO.
AND START SERVIN' UP REAL-DEAL
HOMEMADE PULLED PORK.
HOW DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO BARBECUE?
ALL TRIAL AND ERROR, MAN,
AFTER MY FIRST TRIP TO MEMPHIS
AND I HAD REAL BARBECUE.
I NEVER KNEW WHAT THE BIG DEAL
WAS UNTIL I WENT DOWN THERE.
WHAT KIND OF SMOKER
DO YOU SMOKE ON?
IT'S A 6-FOOT-LONG SOUTHERN
YANKEE BARBECUE ROTISSERIE.
PRETTY LEGIT, THEN.
SHE'S DOIN' HER OWN SAUCE,
TOO.
THAT IS BASED ON
A NORTH CAROLINA
TRADITIONAL VINEGAR SAUCE.
5 CUPS OF KETCHUP,
2 1/2 CUPS CIDER VINEGAR,
1 CUP OF APPLE JUICE.
A LITTLE HONEY?
THEN WE'VE GOT
UNSULFURED MOLASSES.
I LIKE THIS STUFF BETTER.
IT'S HEARTY.
LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
AND THEN THE SEASONING.
YEP, COOKIN' ON
THE BACK OF THE, UH...
LOVELY ASSISTANT
RIGHT HERE.
'93 WINNEBAGO,
NEXT TO THE PORT-A-POTTY.
CAN I GET A SANDWICH?
ONLY IF YOU SQUEEZE
THE PIG THREE TIMES.
IT'S A NEW RULE.
(pig squeaking)
OKAY.
(Grace) WE HAVE THE TRADITIONAL
SQUISHY WHITE BUN,
A NICE, HEALTHY PORTION
OF THE PORK.
LOOK AT THE BARK.
WHAT'S YOUR DRY RUB
MADE OUT OF?
IT'S A PAPRIKA BASE,
BUT I DO ADD
ANCHO, CHIPOTLE,
CAYENNE.
MMM.
SEE? THAT'S THE WAY
TO DO IT.
MMM!
GOOD?
YOU GOT A LITTLE--
WHERE? HERE?
(laughs)
THE WHOLE THING?
GOOD BARBECUE.
THANK YOU.
I THINK YOU CAN STAND UP
NEXT TO SOME OF THE BIG BOYS.
BUT THE BIG BOYS SURE
DON'T HAVE THIS.
OKAY, NACHOS!
(Guy) THE PRIDE
OF THE VESSEL.
GIVE THAT MAN A FORK.
WHAT'S THIS FOR?
MMM.
IT'S THE SALTY CHEESE,
THE SPICY--
THE SPICY JALAPEÑO,
THE BIG CRUNCH OF THE CHIP,
THEN YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF
THE SWEETNESS FROM THE PORK.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD
PULLED PORK.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT IS GOOD.
"HAVE A SEAT.
ENJOY THE MEAT."
I'M A DORK.
BUY MY PORK.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU GOT SWEAT GOIN' ON.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU GET THE "HENWAY?"
WHAT'S THE "HENWAY?"
ABOUT 2 OR 3 POUNDS.
OH, YEAH?!