HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
TOTALLY FRIED.
THAT'S FRENCH
FRY-TASTIC.
AT A 50-YEAR-OLD DINER
IN PHILADELPHIA,
WHERE A FRENCH-TRAINED CHEF
IS FRYING UP HIS OWN TAKE
ON DINER COOKING...
TASTE THE DUCK?
TASTY.
NOT WHAT YOU'D EXPECT
AT A DINER.
AND A CLASSIC
CALIFORNIA DRIVE-IN...
NEXT, PLEASE.
THAT'S KNOCKIN' 'EM DEAD
WITH DEEP-FRIED FALAFEL...
CALIFORNIA FUSION.
THIS IS FANTASTIC
FALAFEL.
AND A SMALL-TOWN CAFÉ
ON THE EDGE OF THE DESERT...
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
WHERE THEY'RE DOING A FRENCH
CLASSIC THE DEEP-FRIED WAY.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN
CHICKEN CORDON BLEU SUBMERGED.
IT DEFINITELY
IS THE CRUNCHIEST.
I MEAN, THAT HAS
A TEXTURE ON THAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-IN AND DIVES."
Closed Captions provided
by Scripps Networks, LLC.
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
ON THIS LEG OF OUR
TOTALLY FRIED TRIP,
WE'RE IN PHILADELPHIA.
NOW WE'RE NOT HERE
TO TALK ABOUT CHEESESTEAKS.
WE'RE HERE TO MEET
A FRENCH-TRAINED CHEF
WHO'S PUTTING A WHOLE NEW SPIN
ON DINER FRIED FARE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
NOT WHAT YOU WOULD
EXPECT AT A DINER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S AWESOME.
DELICIOUS.
AMAZING.
THE BEST.
CHECK OUT THE PULLED-PORK
EMPANADAS,
SPRING ROLLS MADE
WITH HOMEMADE DUCK CONFIT,
SHRIMP-AND-CRAB POT STICKERS
AND FRIED OYSTER SALAD.
IT'S A DINER,
BUT IT'S NOT DINER FOOD.
EVEN THE FRIES
ARE SOMETHING SPECIAL...
THEY MELT
IN YOUR MOUTH.
HAND CUT AND FRIED TWICE
FOR STEAK FRITES,
THE WAY THEY DO IT IN PARIS.
I LOVE THE FRENCH.
I LOVE THE FRENCH,
TOO, BROTHER.
I WOULDN'T HAVE THE FRENCH FRIES
IF IT WEREN'T FOR THE FRENCH,
RIGHT?
YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE A CAREER
IF IT WASN'T
FOR LIVING IN FRANCE.
THIS IS TRUE.
AND AFTER COOKING
SCHOOL IN PARIS,
PETER'S CAREER'S
BACK HOME IN PHILLY
AT THE 50-YEAR-OLD
SILK CITY DINER,
WHICH HAS BEEN
TOTALLY REVAMPED
BY FARMER-TURNED-RESTAURATEUR
MARK BEE--A LIFELONG FOODIE...
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WHO COULDN'T RESIST WHEN
THIS NEIGHBORHOOD LANDMARK
WENT UP FOR SALE.
I USED TO DO THE PLUMBING HERE.
AND AFTER WORKING
IN RESTAURANTS,
YOU WANTED TO BECOME
A RESTAURANT DUDE?
I DO. I LOVE IT.
I LOVE IT.
SO HE RENOVATED IT HIS WAY...
I JUST DON'T WANT IT TO BE
LIKE EVERY OTHER PLACE.
IT'S WHAT I LIKE.
AND BROUGHT IN PETER
TO REDO THE MENU.
HE'S AWESOME. I JUST
LET HIM DO THIS THING.
I JUST MAKE FOOD
I LIKE TO EAT, YOU KNOW?
IT'S LIKE IF I LIKE TO EAT IT--
I THINK MOST PEOPLE LIKE TO EAT
WHAT I LIKE TO EAT.
...LIKE THOSE TOTALLY
HOMEMADE EMPANADAS.
THIS IS JUST LIKE MY ABUELITA--
MY GRANDMOTHER--FANTASTIC.
IT TASTES
JUST LIKE HOME COOKIN'.
IT STARTS WITH A FRESH HAM.
YOU DON'T
USE SHOULDER?
NO, I WAS ALWAYS
MORE OF A LEG MAN
THAN A SHOULDER MAN,
YOU KNOW?
HEY, HONEY,
NICE SHOULDER.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA,
LIKE, CUT THIS UP
AND JUST TOSS 'EM
IN THERE.
CHILI POWDER.
GO FOR IT,
YOU KNOW?
THAT MUCH.
I LOVE THAT.
OH, SO THAT MUCH.
SMOKED PAPRIKA
AND CHIPOTLE POWDER.
YOU CAN DUMP IT
ALL IN THERE.
LET'S GET WILD.
YEAH, YOU KNOW?
WHEN DO WE START
DRINKING BEER?
UH, WELL,
PRETTY SOON, I HOPE.
AFTER FINISHING UP WITH ONION,
GARLIC AND CUMIN,
PETER SIMMERS THE HAM TILL IT
PRETTY MUCH FALLS APART.
HAND SHRED
OR FORK SHRED?
UH, FORK, HAND,
YOU KNOW?
IF YOU CAN GET YOUR FOOT UP
AROUND THERE WITH SOME YOGA,
GET INTO IT.
THERE YOU GO.
HE MIXES IT UP
WITH SWEET POTATO, CILANTRO,
CINNAMON AND BLACK BEANS.
THAT'S TASTY.
I THINK
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I COULD JUST MAKE THAT INTO,
LIKE, A--LIKE, A BALL.
YEAH.
DEEP-FRY IT.
I WOULD JUST
WALK AROUND WITH IT.
INSTEAD, WE'LL ROLL OUT
SOME FRESH DOUGH.
SO WE GOT
OUR LITTLE SKINS.
FILL IT...
AND THAT'S IT.
FOLD IT...
ALL DONE.
AND FRY IT.
HOW LONG
DO THOSE TAKE?
THREE TO FIVE MINUTES.
THEY'LL BE SERVED
WITH A CHIPOTLE-HONEY GLAZE,
PINEAPPLE-HOT PEPPER SALSA
AND CILANTRO, RED ONION
AND LIME ZEST SOUR CREAM.
OH, THAT LOOKS
OUTSTANDING.
WOW. THAT IS AN ORCHESTRA
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S A MELODY
OF JUST GREAT FLAVOR.
AWESOME.
AND AFTER THIS LATIN FAVOR,
PETER'S CRANKIN' OUT
SOME ASIAN SPECIALTIES,
LIKE SHRIMP-AND-CRAB
POT STICKERS.
SACRE BLEU.
SO THIS IS PAN-FRY
AT ITS GREATEST.
AND LOOK HOW FAST WE'RE
PUTTIN' A CRUST ON THAT.
I SEE HOT COMING.
WE GOT THE CRAB,
THE SHRIMP.
REALLY, YOU GET THE TEXTURE
OF THE SHRIMP BACK.
IT DIDN'T
GO TOO FAR.
YOU HAVE SOME OF THE GINGER
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
THAT'S FRENCH
FRY-TASTIC.
AND GET A LOAD
OF THE SPRING ROLLS
FILLED WITH A FRENCH
CLASSIC--DUCK CONFIT.
OH, THE DUCK--WE JUST
SALT IT WITH A LITTLE SALT,
SUGAR, FIVE SPICE--
CHINESE FIVE SPICE--
STAR ANISE,
CINNAMON.
LIKE BUTTAH.
IT'S A HEART ATTACK
IN A BOWL.
YEAH, NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
YOU'RE THE CHEF,
NOT THEIR DOCTOR.
EXACTLY.
SAUTÉED ONIONS,
CABBAGE, PORTOBELLOS,
CARROTS, SOME GINGER,
A LITTLE HOISIN--
KIND OF LIKE A LITTLE ASIAN
BARBECUE SAUCE OF SORTS.
LIKE CHINESE KETCHUP.
CHINESE KETCHUP--I'VE NEVER
HEARD IT CALLED THAT.
THEN WE JUST PUT A LITTLE OF
THE MEAT AND VEG IN THE MIDDLE
AND THEN JUST A LITTLE EGG WASH
RIGHT UP AT THE TOP THERE.
THEN I'LL, LIKE, ROLL 'EM UP
IN SOME CORNSTARCH HERE,
AND THAT'LL DRY UP
THE OUTSIDES.
IT WILL ALSO
ADD A LITTLE CRUNCH.
ALL RIGHT,
SO NOW DEEP-FRY 'EM?
THROW 'EM
IN THE FRYER.
NICE
AND GOLDEN BROWN.
NICE AND TOASTY.
GIVE 'EM A SECOND
TO DRAIN.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
LOOK AT THAT.
AS SOON AS YOU CUT IT OPEN,
YOU CAN SEE DUCK.
TASTY.
TASTE THE DUCK.
DUCK'S NICE. YOU KNOW WHAT
I TASTE? YOU KNOW WHAT I TASTE?
I TASTE
THE FIVE SPICE.
YEAH.
I REALLY PICK UP THE FIVE
SPICE IN THE DUCK.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND IT'S NOT JUST
THE FRIED STUFF.
FOLKS HERE SAY THE ENTIRE MENU
HITS A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL,
EVEN THE DINER BASICS,
LIKE MEAT LOAF
OR THE GRILLED CHEESE.
WELCOME TO ITALY. HERE
IS SOME FRESH-BAKED FOCACCIA.
AND CHECK OUT THE WINGS.
THEY'RE THE BEST WINGS
I EVER HAD--THE BEST.
FRESH WINGS IN A DRY RUB
WITH CUMIN, GARLIC,
PAPRIKA AND MORE.
SO THIS MUST BE ONE OF
THE FRENCH DISHES YOU LEARNED.
YEAH, THIS
IS SOUTHERN FRANCE.
YEAH.
SO THEY BAKE FIRST
FOR HOW LONG?
FOR, LIKE,
45, 50 MINUTES.
AND NOW WE'RE
GONNA FRY 'EM.
JUST, LIKE,
TWO, THREE MINUTES.
JUST HEAT 'EM UP,
CRISP 'EM UP.
THEY'RE GONNA
HEAT UP REALLY FAST.
HEAT 'EM UP,
CRISP 'EM UP.
UH, WE HAVE THE WING
SAUCE RIGHT HERE.
SO THAT IS CHIPOTLE
PEPPERS, BUTTER,
A HOT SAUCE MIXTURE--
A CAYENNE HOT SAUCE--
A LITTLE BIT
OF DIJON MUSTARD.
...AND SRIRACHA.
I'M DYIN'
TO TRY THESE.
WOW, THAT'S SAVORY.
I GOTTA TELL YA...
THAT'S A PRIMO WING,
BRO.
I'D EAT THOSE
EVERY DAY.
...OR THE EMPANADAS
OR THE SPRING ROLLS
OR THE POT STICKERS
OR ANYTHING ON PETER'S MENU.
HAVE YOU TRIED THIS?
JUST ASK THE GROWING
CROWD OF FANS.
WELL, I TRIED A LOT OF THINGS
I NORMALLY WOULDN'T EAT,
AND THEY WERE ALL GOOD.
IT'S NOT JUST AMERICAN FOOD.
IT'S A NICE MIX.
GOOD RESTAURANT FOOD IN A DINER.
AFTER ALL, GOOD FOOD
AT A GOOD PRICE
IS WHAT THE CLASSIC DINER
IS ALL ABOUT.
NOW THROW IN GREAT FOOD
AND A VELVET ELVIS--
HOW CAN YOU MISS?
I LOVE THE PEOPLE.
I LOVE MAKING PEOPLE HAPPY
AND JUST
THROWING A PARTY.
UP NEXT...
TWO SPECIALS.
THE CLASSIC DRIVE-IN
WHERE CALIFORNIANS
ARE JAMMIN' THE JOINT...
THIS LINE JUST KEEPS
LONGER AND LONGER.
ALWAYS CROWDED.
FOR FAST FOOD
MIDDLE EASTERN-STYLE.
I NEVER GET TIRED
OF THE FALAFELS.
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES,"
I'VE TASTED MY WAY
ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
AND ONE OF THE THINGS
I'VE COME TO LEARN
IS TO EXPECT THE UNEXPECTED.
NOW I'D EXPECT TO FIND GREAT
FOOD IN SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA,
BUT WHAT'S UNEXPECTED
IS THAT IT WOULD BE A FRIED
FALAFEL FROM A DRIVE-IN.
TWO SPECIALS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT'S
IN A FALAFEL?
NOT REALLY.
DO YOU CARE?
NO.
I JUST KNOW
IT TASTES GOOD.
THEY'RE BIG AND GREEN AND YUMMY.
THEY'RE MADE OF DEEP-FRIED
CHICK PEAS.
THREE LARGE FALAFELS
AND ONE SMALL FALAFEL.
I NEVER GET TIRED
OF THE FALAFELS.
THEY'VE BEEN FAST FOOD
IN THE MIDDLE EAST FOREVER...
WE ALWAYS
HAD THAT SAYING--
"FEELING AWFUL?
HAVE A FALAFEL."
AND A LOCAL FAVORITE
AT THIS JOINT FOR 40 YEARS.
THERE, SIR.
THANK YOU.
THIS LINE JUST KEEPS
LONGER AND LONGER.
IT'S ALWAYS CROWDED.
IT IS ALWAYS
CROWDED?
ALWAYS.
YOU'VE HAD FALAFELS
BEFORE...
YEAH.
AT A DRIVE-IN?
NO.
IT'S AN ODD COMBINATION.
CALIFORNIA FUSION.
THE FALAFEL BALLS
ARE GOOD.
- FALAFEL SANDWICHES.
-      I GET     THE FALAFEL SALAD.
IT'S MY FATHER'S RECIPE.
IT WILL NEVER CHANGE.
IT JUST--IT'S GOD.
THE WAY IT IS,
AND THAT'S IT.
YEAH, NO ONE CAN TOUCH IT.
IT'S AMAZING.
THIS IS MY DAD.
WOW, IS THAT A DUDE
OF CHARACTER OR WHAT?
HE HAD A PASSION FOR FOOD.
HE LOVED IT--EVERYTHING.
HE WAS ALWAYS
IN THE KITCHEN COOKING.
ANTON NIJMEH BOUGHT
THIS PLACE BACK IN '66
AFTER MOVING HIS FAMILY HERE
FROM THE MIDDLE EAST.
TWO SPECIALS.
MY DAD SEES THIS BURGER JOINT,
AND HE GOES,
"OH, EVERYBODY
HAS BURGERS."
HE'S ALL--THIS IS--HE'S GONNA
GIVE HIS FALAFEL--
OOH, BUT WHO HAS
A FALAFEL DRIVE-IN?
HE WAS GIVING FALAFELS
FOR FREE FOR A LONG TIME.
AND 41 YEARS AGO,
NO ONE KNEW, REALLY,
WHAT A FALAFEL WAS.
HE'D MAKE 'EM TRY IT.
IT WAS LIKE, YEAH,
COME FOR THE BURGER,
BUT HERE,
TRY A FALAFEL.
...BUT TRY IT.
AND THEN IT MADE
THE TRANSITION.
AND THEY DID.
THEY'D TASTE IT AND GO,
"OH, WOW,
THAT IS KIND OF GOOD."
FOUR DECADES LATER,
THE FAMILY'S
KEEPING IT THAT WAY.
I MEAN, THE PLACE IS FABULOUS.
DAUGHTER JOANNE'S
AT THE WINDOW.
NEXT.
THEY LOVE YOU HERE.
AND SON-IN-LAW NASSIF
IS RUNNING THE LINE.
AS FAST AS YOU CAN GET 'EM
FROM HIM AND WRAP 'EM...
WHOO.
IS AS FAST
AS THEY GO?
NUMBER 25, 26, 27, 28.
YOU'RE THE FALAFELNATOR.
LOOK AT HIM. HE'S IN IT.
ALL RIGHT, GUY.
DRY BEANS--WE SOAK
THEM OVERNIGHT.
SO DRY CHICK PEAS.
DRY CHICK PEAS.
WE DRAIN 'EM
AND WASH 'EM.
I'M GONNA GET YA
A BIGGER COLANDER.
IT LOOKS LIKE
SNUFFLEUPAGUS.
WELL, SO MANY
YEARS OF--
ARRRRRR.
WOW, YOU COULD GET RID
OF A BODY IN THIS.
THAT'S THE BASE FOR
THE AWESOME FALAFEL MIX.
IS THAT WHAT
IT'S CALLED?
YEAH.
AWESOME FALAFEL MIX?
YOU HAVE TO BE A MEMBER
OF THE FAMILY
TO KNOW WHAT COMES NEXT.
IT'S MOSTLY HERBS.
OH, SO YOU'RE NOT GONNA
TELL ME WHAT'S IN THIS,
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA
TELL ME THE MIX OF SPICES?
EH, JUST SPICES.
WE GOT CUMIN,
SALT, SUGAR.
...CARAWAY SEEDS, A LITTLE
OF THIS, A LITTLE, YOU KNOW?
AND WHEN YOU MIX IT
WITH THIS, IT'S HEAVENLY.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH--
THAT'S FALAFELNATED?
THAT'S FALAFEL.
WHAT IS THIS THING?
THAT'S A FALAFEL MAKER.
IT MAKES
FALAFEL BALLS.
CAN I DO ONE?
YEAH.
AND YOU SMEAR IT IN?
YEAH, YOU WANT TO PRESS IT
A LITTLE BIT HARD INSIDE.
ALL RIGHT,
GUY IS COOKIN'.
YEAH, I JUST WANT TO BE
CALLED THE FALAFELNATOR.
CAN WE FRY THOSE?
DO WE HAVE A CEREMONY?
NO, IT'S REAL SLOW.
OH, REAL SLOW?
YEAH, OTHERWISE IT WOULD
JUST BREAK APART.
KEEP 'EM LIKE THIS
FOR HALF A MINUTE
TILL THEY JUST
CRISP A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, AND THEN
YOU LET THEM SIT.
YOU LET THEM JUST SOAK
IN THE OIL TILL THEY--
YOU LET THEM COOK FOR,
LIKE, 3 1/2, 4 MINUTES.
LOOK AT THE COLOR
OF THOSE?
HUH?
YOU CAN EAT 'EM STRAIGHT UP...
THAT'S THE BOMB FALAFEL.
OR ON A SALAD OR A PITA
SANDWICH WITH HOMEMADE TAHINI--
THAT'S A SESAME SAUCE--
AND A KILLER HOT SAUCE.
THE MIXTURE OF THOSE
FLAVORS TOGETHER--
THIS IS FANTASTIC
FALAFEL.
THIS ONE'S JUST GOT
THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF SAUCE.
WONDERFUL.
WE USE SOYBEAN OIL,
YOU KNOW,
AND IT FRIES SO HOT
THAT IT DOESN'T HAVE ANY...
'CAUSE IT'S NOT OILY.
NO.
IT'S FALAFELICIOUS.
I'M CHANGING YOUR NAME.
YOU'RE FALAFEL KING.
LET'S MAKE SEVEN MORE.
IT'S AMAZING THE PEOPLE
THAT COME HERE.
YOU GET TRUCKERS.
YOU GET SUITS.
YOU GET KIDS.
KIDS LIKE IT NOW.
IT'S YUMMY.
IT'S ONE OF, YOU KNOW,
THE GREAT PLACES AROUND--
THE LITTLE FINDS--THAT YOU
WON'T GET ANYWHERE ELSE.
IT'S NOT A CHAIN,
AND IT'S REAL FOOD.
AND BEYOND THE FALAFEL...
I'LL HAVE
A LARGE GYRO.
THEY'VE GOT A WHOLE MENU
OF MIDDLE EASTERN
FAST FOOD FAVORITES,
LIKE THE KIFTA KABAB,
THE MIDDLE EASTERN VERSION
OF AN ALL-AMERICAN CLASSIC.
THAT'S
THEIR HAMBURGER.
GROUND BEEF, ONIONS.
ABOUT 600,000 POUNDS
OF PARSLEY.
NO, JUST A BUNCH.
A MAN
AND HIS MACHINE.
RIGHT IN?
YES, PLEASE.
NOW--
SALT, CORIANDER,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT
OF CUMIN...
MMM.
PAPRIKA,
A PINCH OF NUTMEG.
THEN PUT IT
ON THE STICK?
NO, YOU WANT IT ON A SKEWER.
THAT'S A SHISH KABAB.
OH, SO YOU CAN CALL IT A KABAB
EVEN THOUGH IT'S NOT ON A STICK?
THAT'S
A KIFTA KABAB?
KIFTA MEANS SOMETHING YOU PUT IN
YOUR HAND AND YOU MAKE A BALL.
YOU KIFTA IT?
EXACTLY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
GRILL SOME KABABS.
CUT IT IN HALF.
...STUFF IT IN A PITA.
WOW.
TAHINI SAUCE WITH MIXED
VEGETABLE TO IT.
AND THE MAJORITY OF THE PEOPLE
LOVE HOT SAUCE.
AND BON APPÉTIT.
ENJOY.
THAT'S LIKE
A MEDITERRANEAN MEATBALL.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE SEASONINGS REALLY
WORK WELL WITH THE MEAT.
GO AHEAD AND JUST
KEEP WORKING. I'M FINE.
GETTIN' THIRSTY, THOUGH.
SO CHECK OUT THIS
HOUSE SPECIAL.
HOW ARE
THE BANANA SHAKES?
OH, THEY'RE THE BEST.
WHAT IF YOU DON'T
LIKE BANANAS?
WELL, THEN I GUESS YOU DON'T
GET THE BANANA SHAKE.
BA-DUM-BUM.
BUT SERIOUSLY, JOHNNY.
SO WHO MADE UP  THE BANANA SHAKE?
MY FATHER DID.
HE LOVED FRESH FRUIT,
AND THAT WAS THE ONLY ONE
YOU CAN GET YEAR-ROUND.
SLICE IT.
OH, AND THAT'S HOW YOU SLICE
IT--ON THE EDGE OF THE CUP?
NONFAT MILK.
LET ME SEE THAT
ARM STRENGTH.
I LOOK SMALL,
BUT I GOT MUSCLES.
REALLY? YOU CAN
TAKE 'EM DOWN?
YEAH, I CAN. I GOT
THREE BROTHERS, TOO.
MMM, THAT'S LITERALLY BANANAS.
IT GOES SO WELL
WITH FALAFEL AND HOT SAUCE...
IT KIND OF PUTS OUT THE FIRE
IN THE HOT SAUCE, YOU KNOW?
THAT IT'S THE HOT COMBO
ON THE MENU.
THE FALAFEL WITH BANANA
SHAKE SPECIAL.
TWO FALAFEL
WITH BANANA SHAKES?
PEOPLE SAY THEY MOVED AWAY,
AND THEY COME BACK,
"GOD, I JUST HAD TO COME OVER
HERE AND COME TO THIS PLACE.
"I JUST LEFT THE AIRPORT,
AND I'M BACK FOR A WEEK,
AND I'M GONNA BE HERE EVERY DAY
UNTIL I LEAVE TO GET THE--"
YOU KNOW?
...TO GET
MY FALAFEL FIX.
THAT'S WHAT
THEY CALL IT--THE FIX.
...EVEN IF THEY STILL
DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS.
YOU KNOW HOW
THE FALAFELS ARE MADE?
YUMMILY.
YUMMILY?
THEY'RE MADE YUMMILY?
YES.
OHH, I GOTTA
USE THAT.
WELL, THESE ARE ACTUALLY
MADE WITH A LOT
OF YUMMYLICIOUS-ISH-NESS.
YUMMYLICIOUS.
YUMMY-LISH-NESS.
LISH-IS-NESS.
YUMMY-LICIOUSNESS.
NEXT UP, I'M HEADIN'
DOWN THE COAST
TO A SMALL-TOWN CAFÉ...
IT'S THE BEST FOOD IN TOWN.
WHERE FRENCH-FRYING
DOESN'T MEAN POTATOES.
THAT'S FRIED CRUNCH-A-LICIOUS
RIGHT THERE.
SO I'M IN RAMONA, CALIFORNIA,
WHICH IS ABOUT AN HOUR
NORTHEAST OF SAN DIEGO,
RIGHT AT THE GATEWAY
OF THE DESSERT.
NOW IN THE MIDDLE OF TOWN
IS THIS LITTLE JOINT
OWNED BY THE DAUGHTER
OF A LOCAL EGG FARMER...
FRIES READY?
THE KIND OF PLACE YOU'D EXPECT
BASIC CAFÉ COOKING...
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
NOT A HOMEMADE CHICKEN CORDON
BLEU WITH FRESH HOLLANDAISE.
IT'S SPICY AND TENDER.
REALLY GOOD.
AND GET THIS--IT'S DEEP-FRIED.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN
CHICKEN CORDON BLEU SUBMERGED.
WHY DEEP-FRY IT?
IT JUST TASTES BETTER.
IT HAS A CRISPY TEXTURE
TO THE EXTERIOR,
AND IT TASTES
REALLY YUMMY.
SO DOES THE FRIED CHICKEN
AND THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
AND FISH AND CHIPS.
EVEN THE KID-FRIENDLY CHICKEN
STRIPS ARE HOMEMADE,
JUST LIKE ALMOST
EVERYTHING HERE.
THIS IS GOOD.
IT'S THE BEST FOOD IN TOWN.
ANYBODY KNOW WHERE
RAMONA CAFÉ IS?
...A SMALL-TOWN LANDMARK,
A 26-YEAR-OLD LOCAL LEGEND...
IT'S VERY HOMEY.
IS THIS MY TWIN, HUH?
GREAT SERVICE--REALLY FRIENDLY.
RUN BY A LOCAL LEGEND...
ALL RIGHT,
HERE YOU GO.
SONJA VANDERVEEN.
CINNAMON ROLL
FOR YOU.
SONJA IS SUCH A PIE.
SHE'S REALLY SWEET.
WHEN DID THEY
PUT STOPLIGHTS IN?
OH, MY GOD.
THE FIRST SIGNAL
WENT IN IN '79
WHEN I GRADUATED
FROM HIGH SCHOOL.
SONJA LEFT FOR A WHILE
AFTER SHE GRADUATED,
THEN CAME BACK HOME.
20 YEARS AGO,
SHE BOUGHT THIS PLACE
WITH SOME HELP
FROM HER PARENTS,
INCLUDING SOME RECIPES
FROM HER SWISS-BORN MOM.
NOW I GET IT. I DIDN'T KNOW
THERE WAS SWISS INFLUENCE.
OH, YEAH.
DID YOU MAKE CHICKEN CORDON
BLEU WHEN YOU WERE A KID?
DID YOUR MOM
COOK IT FOR YOU?
YES.
SO THIS IS JUST KIND
OF YOUR ADAPTATION.
TRADITIONAL.
SO TAKE ME
THROUGH IT.
OKAY, YOU TAKE
A CHICKEN BREAST,
AND WE CUT IT
IN HALF.
THEN WE PLACE THE PLASTIC
WRAP OVER THE CHICKEN,
BECAUSE WE'RE GONNA
POUND IT OUT.
YOU DON'T WANT IT
TO K-K-K-K-K?
RIGHT. 1/4-INCH THICK.
ALL RIGHT. TAKE
THE SARAN WRAP OFF,
AND PLACE THE HAM
IN THE MIDDLE
AND GRUYèRE
SWISS CHEESE.
YOU REALLY HAVE TO USE
THE GRUYèRE CHEESE?
YES, YOU DO. IT REALLY
ADDS THAT EXTRA FLAVOR.
THAT'S THE TANG.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THEN WHAT
DO YOU DO TO IT?
ROLL IT UP.
AND WE SECURE IT
WITH TOOTHPICKS.
AND I'D EAT THAT
IF I LIKED CHICKEN CEVICHE.
NOW WHEN YOU FIRST
PUT THIS ON THE MENU,
DID PEOPLE
JUST GO BANANAS?
THEY DID. THEY LOVE IT.
OH, MY GOSH.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
BANANAS IS GOOD
WITH CHICKEN CORDON BLEU--
FRIED BANANAS.
MOST PEOPLE JUST BAKE IT AND PUT
THE STUFF ON IT, AND THAT'S IT,
BUT WE'RE
GONNA FRY IT.
RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
DEEP-FRY IT.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
DIP IT IN EGG.
STRAIGHT-UP EGG,
OR IS IT EGG WASH?
IT'S STRAIGHT-UP EGG.
STRAIGHT-UP EGG.
SO IT'S
REALLY GONNA--
THEN WE'RE GONNA DO IT
AGAIN ONE MORE TIME.
OH, WE'RE GONNA
DO THIS BA--OH.
SO YOU REALLY ARE THE COLOSSAL
KING KONG OF CRUST?
DEFINITELY.
DROP IT.
SAY "HAMMER IT."
HAMMER IT.
I'M THE COLOSSAL
KING KONG OF CRUST.
COLOSSAL
OH, WE SET A TIMER?
YOU LOVE YOUR TIMER.
SEE, YOU'RE A BAKER.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
MMM.
THAT CHEESE
REALLY STANDS OUT.
DOESN'T IT?
IT REALLY STANDS OUT IN THAT.
DEFINITELY IS THE CRUNCHIEST.
I MEAN, THAT HAS
A TEXTURE ON THAT.
THE KEY TO THE CRUNCH
IS SONJA'S HOMEMADE BREADING,
MADE FROM HOMEMADE BISCUITS
THAT HAVE BEEN SITTING
AROUND A WHILE.
AND WE DRY 'EM OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS DRIED OUT
A LITTLE BIT?
A LOT. THEY'RE STALE.
SO A LITTLE
BIT OF FLOUR.
SO LIKE A 50-50
MIXTURE?
YEAH, A 50-50
MIXTURE.
PEPPER, A 1/2 TEASPOON
OF CAYENNE,
A TABLESPOON
OF POULTRY SEASONING.
HOW MUCH SALT?
A 1/2 TEASPOON.
AND CAJUN.
NOT TOO SPICY. OKAY.
SONJA USES THAT SAME BREADING
ON HER BUTTERMILK
FRIED CHICKEN.
THAT'S FRIED CRUNCH-A-LICIOUS
RIGHT THERE.
OH, GOOD.
SHE ALSO USES IT ON HER
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK...
VERY GOOD.
WHICH IS REALLY MOIST.
JUICY.
AND HERE'S THE TWIST--
SONJA'S CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK--
INSTEAD OF A SOLID
PIECE OF BEEF--
IS A 50-50 MIXTURE
OF GROUND BEEF AND VEAL.
I THINK THE VEAL AND THE BEEF
IDEA OF CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK--
NICE BIG AND VERY
FLAVORFUL, FLUFFY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A PEPPERY TASTE TO IT.
OKAY.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
THE BREADING'S NOT TOO THICK,
AND THE MEAT IS NICE
AND MOIST INSIDE.
YES.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT IT.
AND THERE'S
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY
TASTE MEAT.
YOU'RE NOT JUST TASTING
FRIED BATTER, FRIED THING.
THE LOCALS SAY IT'S THE SAME
WITH EVERYTHING HERE--
REAL HOME COOKIN'
THAT TASTES LIKE SOMEONE CARES.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE ALL
THE FLAVORS COME TOGETHER,
AND IT TASTES REALLY GOOD.
AND REAL HOME BAKING, TOO.
WHEN WE COME BACK, I'M MAKING
A LITTLE SOMETHING SWEET
TO TOP OFF MY MEAL.
AT THE RAMONA CAFÉ,
THE LUNCH AND DINNER CROWD
IS PACKIN' THE JOINT...
YOU'RE WELCOME. DO YOU GUYS
NEED ANYTHING ELSE RIGHT NOW?
FOR BIG FAVORITES
LIKE CHICKEN CORDON BLEU
AND CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
BUT THIS PLACE IS JUST
AS BIG FOR BREAKFAST...
TOMATOES, BACON, GARLIC,
GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
WITH SOMETHING
CALLED THE KITCHEN SINK.
CHEDDAR CHEESE.
IS THIS GONNA STOP
AT ANY POINT?
JACK CHEESE.
SOME POINT.
THE HAWAIIAN SHORT STACK
WITH PINEAPPLE,
COCONUT AND WHIPPED CREAM
AND STRAWBERRY-CREAM-CHEESE-
STUFFED FRENCH TOAST.
ONE OF THE BEST RESTAURANTS
IN THE AREA, YOU THINK?
DEFINITELY.
OH, THE BEST.
THAT'S LIKE A FOOTBALL.
FOR A OT OF FOLKS,
THE BEST OF THE BEST
ARE THE MASSIVE CINNAMON ROLLS
MADE FRESH EVERY DAY.
I SEE THAT YOU'VE OPENED IT AND
DISPLAYED IT FOR ME SO NICELY.
BUT I HAVEN'T REALLY FELT
THE INVITATION TO EAT IT YET.
OF COURSE NOT.
THAT'S FOR ME
TO TAKE HOME.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO MAKE 'EM?
MY MOM.
YOUR MOM?
YES. YOU PUT
2 CUPS OF MILK IN,
AND THEN YOU THROW IN
4 OUNCES OF MARGARINE.
SLOWLY POUR IT
IN THERE.
IT'S ALL MIXED UP WITH SALT,
SUGAR, YEAST AND FLOUR.
SO THAT'S GONNA WACKA-
WACKA-WACKA FOR FIVE MINUTES?
AND THEN YOU PUT IT
IN A BOWL AND LET IT RISE.
THEN WE THROW THE BIG
GOB OF GOO--DOUGH--
THE BIG GOB OF GOO?
THAT'S WHAT I CALL IT.
IS THAT
A BAKING TERM?
IT GOT HAPPY HERE.
OKAY.
IT GOT HAPPY?
YES.
THE BIG GOB
OF GOO GOT HAPPY?
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT PUTTING
OUT, LIKE, A BIG GOB OF GOO
WORKOUT VIDEO.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, WE GOT
THE MARGARINE...
WOW.
AND WE'RE GONNA SPREAD THAT
ALL OVER THE DOUGH.
WATCH OUT.
AND THEN WE PUT
THE CINNAMON, BROWN SUGAR.
THAT IS A TON
OF CINNAMON AND SUGAR.
IT IS.
WHAT KIND OF NUTS?
PECANS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT
FROM THE FREE.
SERRATED
SO IT DOESN'T TEAR.
DO THEY GO RIGHT
IN THE CENTER?
UM, THAT'S FINE.
HEAVY.
WHAT PART DO YOU EAT FIRST--
THE CENTER OR THE OUTSIDE?
THE CENTER.
THAT'S WHERE YOU GO?
YEAH.
MY SON HUNTER WOULD GO--
OR RYDER--
WOULD GO OUT
OF THEIR MINDS FOR THIS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I GOTTA TAKE HIM ONE OF THESE.
GET A SPATULA, TOO.
SPATULA? OKAY.
YEAH, YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO SCRAPE ME OFF THE CEILING
AFTER THIS MUCH SUGAR.
I'M GOOD FOR TWO
A DAY SOMETIMES.
TWO A DAY?
ONE IN THE MORNING
AND THEN--
YOU NEED TO GET
INTO SOME REHAB, BRO.
WE NEED TO HAVE
A COUNSEL GROUP.
THAT'S THE WHOLE REASON
I HAVEN'T LEFT THIS TOWN
IS BECAUSE
OF THE CINNAMON ROLLS.
SONJA'S SURE NOT
GOING ANYWHERE.
SHE'S HAVING TOO MUCH FUN...
SHE STACKED HER EGGSHELLS.
RUNNING THE PLACE TO GO...
DID HE PUT HIS HAIR ON FOR ME?
IS THAT FOR ME TODAY?
YEAH, FOR YOU.
YOU'RE MONEY.
IN HER HOMETOWN.
ASK ME WHAT
I GET FOR DINNER?
I DON'T KNOW
CINNAMON ROLL KING.
EXACTLY,
A CINNAMON ROLL.
NO, YOU DON'T GET
A CINNAMON ROLL FOR--
YES, I DO.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
NOW THAT PUTS
THE "T" IN TASTY.
THAT MADE NO SENSE.