I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
SO IT'S OVER.
THIS TRIP...
WE'RE HERE. WE'RE HERE.
FAMILY-OWNED JOINTS...
NOW DO YOU GIVE A BIB?
(groans)
A FAST-FOOD PARADISE
IN A CHICAGO SUBURB...
CHEDDAR BURGER--
WELL DONE, BUT JUICY.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S
ALL ABOUT RIGHT HERE.
WHERE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS HAVE
HAD 'EM LININ' UP FOR 24 YEARS.
ARE THERE NO OTHER
RESTAURANTS IN THIS TOWN?
IN MASSACHUSETTS,
THE CLASSIC DINER...
A LOT OF GOOD TOWN GOSSIP
GOIN' ON.
WITH THE CLASSIC MENU...
THEY HAVE TURKEY ON MONDAY
AND ROAST PORK ON TUESDAY.
WHERE THE SAME FAMILY'S
BEEN WORKIN' THE GRILL
FOR THREE GENERATIONS...
SO THIS IS YOUR RECIPE
OR YOUR DAD'S?
BOTH OF US.
AND 67 YEARS
OF MEXICAN HOME COOKIN'...
ORIGINALLY, THE RECIPES WERE
DESIGNED BY MY GRANDMOTHER.
AT THIS SAN DIEGO LEGEND...
WHERE'S THAT BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
WHERE A DAD AND DAUGHTER
ARE MAKIN' FRESH TORTILLAS
THE SAME WAY GRANDDAD DID
BACK IN 1940.
MY DAD DECIDED HE WANTED
TO OPEN UP A TORTILLA SHOP.
THAT IS AWESOME.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON THE FAMILY-OWNED TOUR,
WE'RE RIGHT OUTSIDE OF CHICAGO
WHERE WE FIND
A FIRST-GENERATION PLACE
THAT'S ONLY 800 SQUARE FEET.
HEY, BUT DON'T LET
THE SIZE FOOL YA,
BECAUSE FOR THE LAST 25 YEARS,
THEY'VE BEEN JAMMIN' OUT TONS OF
OFF-THE-HOOK CHICAGO FAVORITES.
I'M GRILLIN' 'EM UP.
YOU WANT MORE PEPPERS?
THIS IS THE BEST BURGER
IN CHICAGO.
CHEDDAR BURGER--
WELL DONE, BUT JUICY.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S
ALL ABOUT RIGHT HERE.
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
ALMOST 20 YEARS.
IT'S GOOD.
CAN WE HAVE THREE FRIES
AND ONE ONION?
LOOKS LIKE A WAR ZONE
BACK HERE.
IT'S QUALITY FOOD.
TASTE-O-VISION.
CHEDDAR POLISH IS GREAT.
CHEDDAR POLISH.
THE ITALIAN BEEF IS GREAT.
THE CHEDDAR BURGER SELLS.
I MEAN, THIS IS THE MENU.
(man) I NEED
ONE ONION RING.
BUT KNOWING THE MENU BY HEART
JUST ISN'T THAT UNUSUAL
AT PARADISE PUP...
DO YOU EVER EAT TWICE A DAY?
OH, YEAH.
CHEDDAR BURGER
WITH CHEESE FRIES.
WHERE FAST FOOD
IS HOME COOKIN'.
WHEN THEY LEAVE HERE,
I WANT PEOPLE TO FEEL
LIKE THEY'VE BEEN TO
SOMEONE'S BACKYARD BARBECUE.
I GOT BURGERS WAITING.
A BACKYARD BARBECUE RUN
BY GEORGE AND TONY MANOS
WHO STARTED THE JOINT
24 YEARS AGO
AFTER JUMPIN' INTO
THE FOOD BIZ AS TEENS.
MY DAD WAS DRIVING BY ONE DAY.
HE SAW A SMALL SIGN,
"FOR SALE" SIGN.
HE CAME. HE SAID, "I GOT
A GREAT SPOT FOR YOU GUYS."
AND 24 YEARS LATER,
THEY STILL DON'T WANT ANYONE
ELSE WORKIN' THE GRILL.
WE HAVE TO BE HERE.
YEAH, WE HAVE TO BE HERE.
THE BROTHERS HAVE
TO BE HERE.
TILL NOW.
I BETTER NOT HEAR ANY COMPLAINTS
ABOUT THAT HOT DOG.
I'M COOKIN' IT.
(man) ALL RIGHT.
AND WHAT THEY'RE DOIN' HERE
IN AN 800-SQUARE-FOOT JOINT...
THANK YOU.
IS TRADITIONAL
CHICAGO FAST FOOD
THE WAY IT OUGHTA BE...
ONE MEDIUM RASPBERRY ICED TEA.
ONE MEDIUM COKE.
FROM POLISH SAUSAGE
TO TOTALLY LOADED CHICAGO DOGS,
HOMEMADE ITALIAN BEEF,
AND CHECK OUT THEIR BURGERS.
IT MAKES A BIG MESS, SO YOU
GOTTA HAVE ABOUT 20 NAPKINS
READY TO GO
WHEN YOU'RE EATING IT.
EXPERIENCED MAN CAN HOLD
WITH ONE HAND.
THE CHEDDAR BURGER...
RIGHT.
IS, LIKE, THE MAC DADDY
OF ALL BURGERS.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S JUST A GREAT
PIECE OF MEAT.
1/3-POUND PATTY.
FRESH, NEVER FROZEN.
LOOK HOW HOT THAT IS.
THAT'S CHAR-GRILLED
RIGHT THERE, BABY.
THAT'LL GET A NICE
LITTLE CRUST ON IT.
WHAT TEMPERATURE DO YOU THINK
THAT TOP IS RIGHT THERE?
ABOUT 750.
OKAY, OKAY.
SO IT'S OVER.
THERE WE GO.
(imitates slap)
LOOK AT THAT.
WHAT I LIKE
IS THAT IT'S JUST GOT
A NICE SEAR ON THE OUTSIDE.
AND A TWIST BUN.
ARE WE GRILLIN' THE BUNS?
ABSOLUTELY.
YES, WE DO.
I'M PUTTING THE SOFT CHEDDAR
ON THE TOP OF THE BUN.
SOFT CHEDDAR.
RIGHT,
THE WISCONSIN ... CHEDDAR.
RIGHT ON TOP.
MARRY IT TOGETHER.
THERE WE GO.
PICKLES, LETTUCE, TOMATO
AND SOME OF THESE
MOLTEN HOT ONIONS.
NOW DO YOU GIVE A BIB?
NO, NO BIBS, MAN.
OH!
THAT IS JUICY.
OH. YOU GUYS
HAVE A SHOWER?
WE'LL HOSE YOU DOWN
IN THE BACK.
IT'S A REALLY STRONG CHEDDAR,
AND IT'S REALLY STRONG BEEF,
AND THE ONION'S JUST
ON TOP OF THAT.
I TASTE A NICE GREAT CHARRED
TASTE. THE CHEESE IS GREAT.
WE'VE BEEN STANDING HERE AWHILE,
YES, WAITING FOR A CHAR BURGER.
IS THIS LIKE THIS JUST
BECAUSE IT'S SATURDAY?
NO.
THIS IS EVERY DAY?
A NICE SUNNY DAY, YEAH.
OH, THIS IS BANANAS.
AND IN THIS CASE,
BANANAS IS GOOD.
...SO'S THE POLISH SAUSAGE...
LOOK AT THAT.
TOPPED WITH GRILLED ONIONS...
MMM. WOW.
THE REAL-DEAL CHICAGO DOGS.
MUSTARD, RELISH,
FRESH CHOPPED ONION.
TOMATOES. FRESH CUCUMBER.
YOU'RE GONNA GET A HOT DOG
THAT YOU'RE NOT GONNA FORGET.
THAT'S CELERY SALT.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE BEEN
TO THE SALAD BAR.
I KNEW YOU COULD DO IT.
THAT'S TASTY.
THAT WAS DELICIOUS, MAN.
AND THEY'RE DOIN' THAT
OTHER CHICAGO CLASSIC--
ITALIAN BEEF
ENTIRELY FROM SCRATCH.
THIS IS THE TOP BUTT.
TOP BUTT.
PUT THE SALT, PEPPER.
SO YOU'RE COUNTING ON THIS
NOT ONLY COOKING
AND SEASONING THE MEAT,
BUT THIS IS ALSO FORTIFYING IT
TO MAKE THE JUICES.
EXACTLY. THAT'S WHY YOU
WANT TO SPICE IT UP.
RIGHT.
THIS IS THE OREGANO.
OREGANO, OKAY.
OF COURSE. SPECIAL INGREDIENT
RIGHT HERE--GARLIC JUICE.
GARLIC JUICE?
SMELL THAT.
OH, YOU DON'T WANT TO TASTE IT.
YOU WANT TO SMELL IT.
OH, YEAH.
OH. HOW DO YOU GET THAT?
I THINK YOU ONLY
FIND THAT IN CHICAGO.
AND THEN YOU PUT IT
IN THE OVEN
AND COOK IT FOR ABOUT
FOUR HOURS REALLY SLOW.
NOW WE TAKE IT OUT
AND SLICE IT.
SLICE IT UP THIN.
THIN.
WHERE YOU CAN SEE
RIGHT THROUGH IT.
I CAN STAY HERE AND SLICE
THAT FOR YOU, IF YOU WANT.
THAT'S OKAY.
THAT IS TASTY.
OOH, HOT.
AAH!
OW, YES.
YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
OKAY, TAKE IT
AND GIVE IT A BATH.
ON THIS LIKE THIS?
ON DOWN.
DOWN?
SO THIS IS THE SAME JUICE--
THIS IS THE HERB MIXTURE
THAT WE RUBBED
ON THE MEAT EARLIER.
RIGHT.
EXACTLY.
WE ROASTED IT.
WHAT ABOUT THE PEPPERS?
OH, YEAH. NO,
I'M COMIN' OVER HERE.
OKAY.
...PEPPERS.
SOME VEGETABLES IN THERE.
HO HO!
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
SEE, THAT'S WHY YOU CAME
TO CHICAGO.
THAT'S WHY YOU CAME
TO CHICAGO, GUY.
WOW.
OH, THAT IS SO GOOD.
UNH!
ALL THOSE HERBS AND SPICES.
IT'S THE THIN SLICING, TOO...
RIGHT.
EXACTLY.
THAT REALLY
MAKES A DIFFERENCE.
EXACTLY.
IT'S GOOD, BUT IT'S MESSY.
THIS IS GOOD.
I SHOULD BE
AT THE HEALTH CLUB RIGHT NOW,
BUT I'M HERE EATING
THIS DOUBLE CHEDDAR BURGER.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
...WHICH IS WHY
THEY KEEP LININ' UP...
ARE THERE NO OTHER RESTAURANTS
IN THIS TOWN?
(woman) THREE FRIES
AND AN ONION RING TO GO.
AT A CHICAGO-AREA LEGEND...
YOU CAN GO STAND
IN LINE THERE,
AND YOU CAN HEAR 'EM TALKIN'
CHICAGO SPORTS, LIKE...
OH, YOU CAN PICK UP
ON THE--
YOU CAN HEAR
SOME LOCALS--
NO, YOU'D MISS THAT
IF YOU DIDN'T GO.
YOU'D MISS ALL THE SMACK?
THREE CHEDDAR BURGERS,
THREE CHEDDAR DOGS AND A FRY.
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT THAN,
YOU KNOW,
YOUR REGULAR HOT DOG STAND,
AND IT'S QUALITY FOOD.
STILL MADE BY A COUPLE
OF BROTHERS...
TWO PLAIN TO GO.
COMMITTED TO DOIN' IT RIGHT.
PLAIN, SIMPLE INGREDIENTS.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
KEEPIN' IT FRESH.
IT'S ALL IN OUR FOOD.
IT'S ALL IN THE QUALITY
OF OUR FOOD.
UP NEXT...
IT'S A PIECE OF HISTORY.
WE'RE HEADIN'
FOR MASSACHUSETTS...
HOW YOU DOIN', GENTLEMEN?
WHERE THE SAME FAMILY'S BEEN
TURNING OUT THE CLASSICS...
THAT'S LIKE MOTHER
USED TO MAKE.
IN A CLASSIC...
I ALWAYS LIKED DINERS.
FOR 60 YEARS.
HOLY MOLY.
YOU LIKIN' IT?
IT'S GOOD, MAN.
IN 1947, A TRUCK DRIVER
NAMED CHARLIE TURNER
FROM WORCESTER, MASSACHUSETTS,
WAS INSPIRED TO BUY A DINER.
ALONG WITH HIS 12-YEAR-OLD SON,
THEY LEARNED HOW TO COOK
ON OPENING DAY.
SO 60 YEARS LATER,
CHARLIE'S DINER IS STILL RUNNIN'
STRONG IN A NEW LOCATION.
THE 12-YEAR-OLD SON--
WELL, NOW HE'S A FATHER,
AND HE'S RUNNING THE DINER
WITH HIS SON.
WE'RE HERE. WE'RE HERE.
I'M GOIN' TO WORK.
FOR CHARLIE TURNER
AND HIS SON STEVE,
WORK'S ALWAYS BEEN
SOMETHING TO LOVE...
OH, IT'S A PLEASURE.
THANK YOU, IRA.
RUNNING A CLASSIC DINER
THE CLASSIC WAY...
GOOD PEOPLE.
THERE'S ALWAYS A LOT OF GOOD
TOWN GOSSIP GOIN' ON.
GOOD PORTIONS.
FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
WITH A BIG MENU
OF BIG FAVORITES.
I USUALLY HAVE THE STEAK TIPS.
WHAT ARE
THEY MARINATED IN?
BOURBON MARINADE SAUCE.
IT'S GOOD. GREAT TEXTURE.
LIKE, THE FOOD IS MUCH BETTER
THAN, LIKE, FAST FOOD.
LIKE, THE FRENCH FRIES
ARE THICKER,
AND IT JUST TASTES SO GOOD.
AWESOME. THE FISH IS ABOUT
AS FRESH AS IT GETS.
WELL, WE WANTED THE KIDS
TO HAVE AN EXPERIENCE
AND SEE WHAT A DINER IS LIKE.
DINERS ARE DINERS.
I ALWAYS LIKED DINERS.
FOOD'S GREAT. I MEAN,
IT'S, YOU KNOW, DINER FOOD.
(Guy) WAS YOUR GRANDFATHER
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
BEFORE HE GOT THIS DINER?
(man) NO.
HE WAS A TRUCK DRIVER.
BASICALLY, HE DROVE
THROUGH THE...
AND HE THOUGHT, MAYBE THIS WOULD
BE A GREAT PLACE FOR A DINER,
AND NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
HE OPENED UP A DINER.
UH, I WORKED WITH MY FATHER
FOR 26 YEARS,
AND THEN I RAN THIS PLACE
BY MYSELF ANOTHER 26 YEARS.
HOW'S YOUR FISH SANDWICH?
THEN STEVE JUMPED IN
TO HELP HIS DAD KEEP
THE FAMILY BUSINESS GOIN'.
THANK YOU.
OH, YOU'RE WELCOME.
AND AFTER DEVELOPERS
WENT AFTER THEIR OLD LOCATION
IN WORCESTER,
CHARLIE AND STEVE DECIDED
TO MOVE THE ENTIRE DINER
15 MILES TO SPENCER.
THAT WAS ONE YEAR AGO,
AND FOLKS COULDN'T BE HAPPIER
TO HAVE 'EM.
THEY CAME TO US.
YOU DON'T FIND MANY RESTAURANTS
THAT MOVE TO YOU.
NO, NO, NO. EXACTLY.
AND I'D ALWAYS MAKE
A SPECIAL TRIP
FROM NORTHBRIDGE
UP TO WORCESTER.
IT WAS ABOUT
A 30-, 35-MINUTE RIDE.
AND JUST YESTERDAY,
I FOUND OUT THAT THE DINER
WAS REOPENED UP HERE,
SO NOW WE MADE A 50-MINUTE RIDE.
HIS NORM IS
BLUEBERRY PANCAKES.
I GET BLACK STACK REGULAR.
WOW. FANTASTIC.
DO YOU USUALLY EAT YOUR
FRENCH TOAST WITH YOUR HAND?
YEAH.
THAT'S YOUR FAVORITE WAY?
I LOVE EATIN' STUFF
WITH MY HANDS.
HOWEVER YOU EAT IT,
CLASSIC DINER BREAKFAST
IS A BIG DEAL HERE,
ESPECIALLY
THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
SO THIS IS YOUR RECIPE
OR YOUR DAD'S?
BOTH OF US.
BOTH OF YOURS.
YEP.
DID YOU MAKE
THE CORNED BEEF?
YEP. BOILED THIS
UP YESTERDAY
FOR THE CORNED BEEF
AND CABBAGE.
SO WE DON'T WANT TO GO
TOO FAST ON THIS, DO WE?
YEAH, THAT WAY WE DON'T
COOK THE LITTLE MACHINE.
MY FATHER NEVER COOKED
AN EGG IN HIS LIFE.
WE BOTH LEARNED TOGETHER.
YOU KNEW THE PART OF NOT
PUTTIN' THE SHELL WITH THE EGG.
NO.
IN OTHER WORDS, WE LEARNED THAT
AFTER A COUPLE OF CUSTOMERS.
AFTER A COUPLE PEOPLE.
WE LEARNED.
WHAT ARE WE DOIN' NOW,
ADDIN' SOME EGGS?
KEEP GOIN'.
OKAY. I'M SORRY.
THE QUESTION--
IT'S KIND OF THE THING ABOUT
BEIN' THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
I NORMALLY ASK THESE
ANNOYING QUESTION THINGS.
WELL, THAT'S YOUR JOB.
POTATOES A GO.
WHAT'S THE RATIO ON
THE CORNED BEEF AND POTATO?
3 TO 1.
IT'S MOSTLY ALL CORNED BEEF.
HOLY MOLY.
NOW DO WE THROW ANY SEASONING
INTO THIS OR--
NO. I'LL LEAVE IT
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
WHAT YOU SEE IS WHAT YOU GET.
LET'S HASH IT UP.
YOU CAN'T SELL HASH
BEFORE ITS TIME.
IT HAS, LIKE,
A BORN-ON DATE.
IT DOES? WOW. SO THAT
WENT A LOT CRISPIER.
(Steve) YES, IT DID.
THAT'S THE CRUNCH
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THE CRUNCH.
MMM. NICE AND SOFT.
YEP.
NICE LITTLE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE.
HOT.
REALLY HAS GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
A LITTLE CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE
AND NICE AND RED ON THE INSIDE--
JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
EVERYTHING'S ALWAYS FRESH.
EVERYTHING'S COOKED DAILY.
...LIKE CHARLIE'S
HAND-CUT FRENCH FRIES.
THEY'RE FRESHER.
THEY'RE NOT FROZEN.
THEY'RE NOT STALE.
THEY'RE PERFECT.
BUT FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
PERFECT FRIES...
MMM. THEY LOOK SO GOOD.
OR ANY OTHER DISH
ARE JUST PART OF THE PACKAGE.
HOW YOU DOIN', GENTLEMEN?
EVEN IN THE NEW HOMETOWN,
THE PLACE FEELS LIKE FOLKS
HAVE BEEN MEETIN'
EACH OTHER HERE FOREVER.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE THAT
SHE WILL EAT HER ENTIRE MEAL,
BECAUSE CHARLIE
WILL GET AFTER HER.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET
CHARLIE STARTED, DO YA?
NO.
WE FEED THE SAME
PEOPLE EVERY DAY.
SO CHARLIE'S BIG ON VARIETY...
AWESOME.
MAKING EVERYTHING
FROM FRIED CLAMS
TO ZITI WITH ITALIAN SAUSAGE
TO HOMEMADE MAC 'N' CHEESE
AND ESPECIALLY THE SPECIALS.
THEY HAVE TURKEY ON MONDAY
AND ROAST PORK ON TUESDAY.
WEDNESDAY IS ROAST BEEF,
AND THEN THEY HAVE
CORNED BEEF ON ANOTHER DAY
AND THEN FISH-AND-CHIPS
ON FRIDAY.
OH, SO IT'S NOT LIKE YOU KNOW
THE MENU OR ANYTHING.
OH, NO.
AND THEY RUN THE TURKEY POT PIE
WHEN THE WEATHER GETS COLD.
OKAY, LET'S CRANK.
COOKED CARROTS.
OKAY.
I MEAN, THOSE ARE SOME
JUMBO CHUNK OF TURKEY.
YEP. SOMEBODY'S GONNA
GET VERY LUCKY.
THEN HE MAKES
HIS OWN TURKEY GRAVY.
AND THIS GRAVY--
YOU'RE GONNA SAY "WOW."
I CAN REPAIR IT, CAPTAIN.
SO HOW LONG'S
SHE RUN FOR, CHARLIE?
THAT'LL RUN FOR ONE HOUR
TILL WE GET SOME COLOR.
IT'LL BE SERVED UP OVER
HOMEMADE MASHED POTATOES.
JUST PUT IN
ABOUT THIS MUCH BUTTER
AND JUST A SMASH OF SALT.
I DON'T EVEN WANT YOU TO TASTE
THE SALT, BUT IT'S IN THERE.
HOLY MOLY.
I DON'T KNOW WHICH SIDE
TO ATTACK FIRST.
(laughs) YOU'D BETTER HOPE
IT DOESN'T ATTACK YOU.
YOU LIKIN' IT?
IT'S GOOD, MAN.
JUST LIKE MOTHER
USED TO MAKE.
AND JUST LIKE
MOTHER USED TO GO TO
WHEN SHE WASN'T
DOIN' THE COOKIN'.
IT'S A PIECE OF HISTORY.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY THAT, YOU
KNOW, THE KIDS CAN EXPERIENCE
WHAT MY MOTHER AND MY FATHER--
HOW THEY USED TO DINE.
IT'S JUST A, YOU KNOW,
A GREAT ATMOSPHERE
AND SOME TIME TO SPEND
WITH THE FAMILY.
...AT A JOINT RUN BY A FAMILY.
OKAY.
GRANDPA CHARLIE
HAS THE KITCHEN COVERED.
THIS GOES DOWN
TO RALPH AT THE END.
SON STEVE IS WORKIN' THE GRILL.
GRANDSON CHARLIE IS GROWIN' UP
IN THE DINER.
HE'S GONNA BE THE FOURTH
GENERATION, I HOPE.
THAT'S AWESOME.
GUY, I USUALLY DO
FOUR THINGS AT A TIME.
YOU GOT ME DOIN' ONE
AT A TIME.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO COOK THAT WAY.
WE WOULD HAVE BROUGHT
FOUR CAMERAS NEXT TIME.
I'M GOIN' TO WORK.
FRAME THIS ONE.
NEXT UP, WE'RE ROLLIN'...
VERY GOOD.
TO SAN DIEGO
FOR MEXICAN HOME COOKIN'...
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S BEEN ALL IN THIS FAMILY
FOR ALMOST 70 YEARS.
WHO WANTS ANOTHER TAQUITO?
(all) I DO! ME!
I LOVE MEXICAN FOOD.
I MEAN, I REALLY LOVE
MEXICAN FOOD.
NOW IT MIGHT BE GROWIN' UP
IN CALIFORNIA MOST OF MY LIFE,
BUT WHATEVER THE CASE,
WE GOTTA CHECK THIS PLACE OUT
IN SAN DIEGO
THAT MAKES THEIR OWN TORTILLAS,
HAND-ROLLS THEIR TAQUITOS
AND IS A THIRD-GENERATION
FAMILY RESTAURANT
THAT HAS A LOYAL FOLLOWING
FOR OVER 67 YEARS.
MICHAEL, NUMBER 20.
(man) THANK YOU.
IT'S THE REAL STUFF.
I HAD A TACO.
THAT IS GOOD.
YOU LIKE THAT ONE?
IT'S 8:10 IN THE MORNING.
IT'S--IT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOOD ANY TIME.
OH, I THINK I'M GONNA GO
WITH THE CARNE ASADA BURRITO.
CAN'T GO WRONG.
THEY HAVE THE BEST
MEXICAN FOOD IN TOWN.
IT FEELS LIKE IT'S BEEN
THAT WAY HERE FOREVER--
FOLKS FLOCKING IN
FOR RIGHTEOUS TAMALES,
CHILE RELLENOS,
ENCHILADAS AND PLENTY MORE.
I THINK I WANT A BURRITO,
BUT I CAN'T DECIDE WHICH.
IT WAS ALL STARTED BACK IN 1940
BY RALPH PESQUEIRA'S FATHER
WHO LEARNED HIS COOKING FROM
HIS MEXICAN-BORN PARENTS...
ORIGINALLY, THE RECIPES WERE
DESIGNED BY MY GRANDMOTHER.
A TRADITION
OF REAL HOME COOKING
RALPH AND HIS DAUGHTER JENNIFER
ARE CARRYING ON...
WELL, I GOT A LITTLE
GARLIC, SALT, CUMIN.
REAL-DEAL RECIPES
FOR EVERYTHING...
A LITTLE LIME JUICE.
THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT LIME JUICE, YES.
LIKE THE SEASONED
SHREDDED BEEF.
I COULD DO
THAT WHOLE THING.
AND THEN THIS
IS THE CHICKEN?
THIS IS THE CHICKEN
MIXED IN WITH SAUCE AND PEPPERS
AND COOKED THAT WAY.
WHERE'S THAT BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
EVEN THE BEANS AND SALSA
ARE MADE FRESH,
AND GUACAMOLE, OF COURSE.
JUST BASIC LIME.
CILANTRO, TOMATO,
SALT, PEPPER.
THAT'S IT, EXACTLY.
THAT'S GOOD.
...SO ARE THE SOFT
CORN TORTILLAS,
WHICH GOT THE WHOLE DEAL
STARTED IN THE FIRST PLACE.
MY DAD DECIDED HE WANTED
TO OPEN UP A TORTILLA SHOP.
HAD HE MADE TORTILLAS
AT HOME?
HE HAD NEVER MADE
TORTILLAS AT HOME.
MY GRANDMOTHER HAD. WE STARTED
MAKING TORTILLAS BY HAND,
AND THEN A GROUP
OF HIS FRIENDS DECIDED
THAT THEY WOULD MAKE
A TORTILLA MACHINE,
AND THE FIRST LITTLE
MACHINE WAS BUILT.
TODAY'S MACHINE'S
BIGGER AND FASTER,
BUT YOU STILL
GOTTA START BY HAND...
LET'S PLAY CHECKERS.
YOU GET THAT.
OKAY, NOW WE TURN?
THAT'S IT, RIGHT. EXACTLY.
THERE WE GO.
MIXING TO SOFTEN UP THE HARD
SHELLS OF THE CORN.
I LIKE THE FLIP-FLOP
AND THE HOT WATER AND THE CORN.
I KNOW.
AAH!
(laughs)
IT GETS WASHED.
IT GETS DUMPED IN.
INSIDE THAT GRINDER IS THIS.
IT'S ALL MECHANICAL
AND IT'S ALL MACHINE,
BUT THEY PUT A BIG
LAVA ROCK IN IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YEAH, THAT SOUNDS SMART.
BUT IF YOU WANT
TO REACH UP THERE,
YOU CAN ACTUALLY FEEL
THE STONE IN THERE.
NEXT ON "THE DUMBEST THINGS
DONE ON TV"...
OH, YEAH, I FELT IT.
NOTICE HOW FINE THAT IS.
THAT'S WHAT GIVES YOU
A REAL GOOD TORTILLA.
WOW.
THAT'S REALLY GOT,
LIKE, REAL FLAVOR.
THAT'S ABOUT 12 POUNDS
OF MASA RIGHT THERE.
WHAT A FOOD FIGHT
WE COULD HAVE HERE.
JUST DROP IT. THAT'S IT.
THE TORTILLA COMES OFF.
THAT'S A 6 3/4-INCH TORTILLA.
IT COMES AROUND,
DROPS DOWN IN HERE.
FLOP OVER.
FLOPS OVER.
COMING DOWN HERE.
OH, MAN.
THAT IS AWESOME.
JUST STACK 'EM
12 IN A STACK.
FOUR, FIVE...
ONE--AAH! TWO, THREE...
SIX... WAIT A SECOND.
FANTASTIC.
EXCELLENT.
THEY HAVE THE BEST
TORTILLAS IN TOWN.
THEY MAKE 'EM FRESH EVERY DAY,
AND WHEN YOU'RE STANDING
IN LINE, THEY'LL THROW YA ONE.
RIGHT FROM THIS LINE...
OKAY, PICK ONE.
TO THIS ONE...
(woman) THANK YOU.
HAVE A GOOD DAY. ENJOY.
THEY'RE BEING FILLED
WITH BEEF, CHICKEN, FISH,
DIPPED IN A RED CHILE SAUCE
TO MAKE CHEESE ENCHILADAS,
CUT UP AND FRIED
FOR HOMEMADE CHIPS...
YOU CAN'T GET CHIPS
LIKE THIS ANY PLACE ELSE.
OR ROLLED AND FRIED TO MAKE ONE
OF MY FAVORITES--A TAQUITO.
OKAY, SO WE TAKE A LITTLE
BIT OF THE MIXTURE.
OKAY. YOU'RE GONNA
EAT THESE, SO...
OH, WELL, NOW YOU TELL ME.
OVER?
OVER AND PULL BACK.
OKAY.
NOW ROLL IT TIGHT.
GOOD. VERY GOOD.
OKAY.
NOW YOUR TOOTHPICK
YOU'RE GONNA PUT IN
APPROXIMATELY 1 INCH DOWN.
OF ALL THE THINGS
YOUR DAD INVENTED,
HE DID NOT INVENT
THE TOOTH-A-PICK-A-RAMMER
WHERE YOU WOULD JUST
TAKE YOUR TAQUITO
AND SC--WACKA!
PICK UP YOUR TAQUITOS.
SO WE DON'T WANT 'EM
TO BE SUPER CRUNCHY CRISPY
WHERE THEY FALL APART.
NO.
OKAY.
NOW WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IS
YOU WANT TO TAKE YOUR FINGERS
AND CRACK IT OPEN AND ROLL IT
LIKE THAT TOWARDS YOU A BIT.
SO I WANT YOU TO LAY
YOUR SALSA IN IT LIKE THAT.
NOW THIS IS
THE SALSA YOU MAKE?
RIGHT.
THERE'S A LOT OF ROLLIN'
WITH THE FINGERS.
AH! TOO THICK.
THAT ONE'S YOURS, RALPH.
OKAY. A SCOOP OF GUACAMOLE
IN EACH ONE 'EM.
NOW THE CHEESE--SET IT
ACROSS LIKE THIS, YOU SEE?
OH, IT'D TAKE ONE GUY
ABOUT A DAY TO MAKE 'EM.
NAW. ONCE YOU GET GOING AT THIS,
IT GETS PRETTY FAST.
NOW LETTUCE, AND THAT'S IT.
WOW.
HOW DO I APPROACH IT?
YOU GO IN?
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
ON?
MMM. MAN, THEY'RE GOOD.
THESE SHOULD JUST BE CALLED
"HOME OF THE GREAT TAQUITO."
...UNTIL YOU TRY
THE CHILE RELLENOS
OR THE HANDMADE TAMALES...
OH, THOSE ARE, LIKE, INCREDIBLE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
UH-OH. YOU CAN TELL
WHICH ONE THE GRINGO MADE.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
IT'S THE LONG ONE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
FOR 67 YEARS,
EL INDIO IN SAN DIEGO
HAS BEEN CRANKIN' OUT
HOMEMADE EVERYTHING.
GOOD AS IT WAS
30 YEARS AGO.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
EVERYTHING DOWN HERE
IS SPECTACULAR.
FROM TORTILLAS TO ENCHILADAS
TO TAQUITOS.
12 COLD BEEF TAQUITOS?
YES.
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'
WITH COLD ONES?
THE KIDS EAT THEM
FOR SNACKS.
AND CHECK OUT THE HANDMADE
CHILE RELLENOS.
THIS IS A CALIFORNIA
GREEN CHILE PEPPER.
AND THIS IS JUST CHEDDAR
CHEESE, MILD CHEDDAR?
JUST REGULAR
MILD CHEDDAR CHEESE.
ONE WRAPS IT ONE WAY.
AND THE OTHER ONE WRAPS IT
THE OTHER WAY, RIGHT.
SO WE'RE USING ALL
OF OUR COOKING TECHNIQUES.
WE'RE USING
DOG ON A STICK, TEMPURA,
MEXICAN FOOD
AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
YOU GOT IT.
VERY NICE.
EGG FLOUR BATTER.
SO IS IT EGG WHITES
OR IS IT THE WHOLE EGG?
IT'S THE WHOLE EGG.
'CAUSE IT DOESN'T
LOOK THAT YELLOW.
IT'S THE FLOUR
THAT DOES THAT.
NOW TWIST IT A LITTLE BIT.
THERE YOU GO.
HUH?
YEAH.
DID I DO OKAY?
ALL RIGHT.
I GOTTA TELL YA
THE PEPPERS ARE MONEY.
IT'S NOT JUST
THE CHILE RELLENOS
THAT THEY'RE
HAND-WRAPPIN' HERE.
THEY'RE ALSO DOIN' TAMALES
WITH THE FRESH-GROUND CORN
CALLED MASA.
SIDE TO SIDE?
YEAH, GO SIDE TO SIDE.
THESE ARE BEEF?
THAT'S BEEF.
OKAY.
OKAY, THAT'S GOOD.
NOW KINDA SPREAD IT AROUND.
PUT AN OLIVE IN IT.
NOW WHY THE OLIVE?
TRADITIONAL. PEOPLE,
WHEN THEY MADE TAMALES,
ALWAYS ADDED
AN OLIVE TO IT.
ROLL IT UP?
BUT ISN'T IT SUPPOSED
TO OVERLAP ITSELF?
IT WILL. YOU GOT IT.
LIKE THAT?
THERE YOU GO.
FOLD THE ENDS IN.
OKAY.
OKAY, NOW WRAP IT TIGHT.
AND DOWN.
WRAP IT TIGHT.
AND YOU'RE PRETTY CLOSE.
SHE'S GONNA BE UNDOIN' THESE
AND TAKIN' 'EM APART
AND GOIN', "WHOEVER"...
YOU CAN TELL WHICH ONE
THE GRINGO MADE.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
IT'S THE LONG ONE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
NOW HOW MANY TAMALES CAN
THE AVERAGE TAMALE MAKER MAKE?
SHE'LL MAKE ABOUT 100--
OVER 100.
OVER 100 IN ABOUT, UM...
UNA HORA.
UNA HORA. ONE HOUR.
IT'S THE LITTLE
TWISTY-TWISTY THING
THAT SHE'S GOT GOIN'.
YEAH.
AND THEN SHE HAS THE...
NOW THEY'RE GONNA GO
INTO A STEAM JACKET?
WE'VE GOT
A BIG STEAM POT.
NOW REMOVE THE HUSK,
PILE ON THE TOPPINGS.
THAT IS A TAMALE,
AND THEN SOME.
THAT IS A TAMALE.
CAN I HAVE A BITE?
YEAH.
YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK IS SO GOOD
IS THE MASA. THAT'S GOOD.
SO HOW'S YOUR TAMALE?
IT'S GREAT.
AND JUST LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT DRAWS THE CROWDS HERE,
IT'S STILL AS GOOD
AS IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
HOME COOKIN'
FROM THE SAME FAMILY
FOR ALMOST 70 YEARS.
VERY CASUAL. VERY FRIENDLY.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE
TO GET A QUICK LUNCH.
IT'S LIKE A FAMILY-TYPE PLACE.
SO WOULD YOUR DAD
BE HAPPY
WITH WHAT YOU'VE DONE,
WITH WHAT'S GOING ON NOW?
HE'D BE ELATED.
THIS IS JUST--
I MEAN, HE'D JUST BE...
YEAH.
THERE ARE OTHER PLACES
TO EAT.
NO.
WHO WANTS ANOTHER TAQUITO?
(all) I DO! ME!
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
SEVEN, EIGHT,
NINE, HOT, TEN.
WATCH THIS.
HA!