HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(man) OKAY, PICKUP.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
IT'S NOT YOUR REGULAR BREAKFAST.
BIG BREAKFAST...
I'M SO EXCITED.
THE HANDS ARE FLYIN'.
THE KANSAS CITY JOINT
WHERE THEY'RE LININ' UP...
OKAY, GUYS, LET'S GO.
FOR TOTALLY HOMEMADE HASH...
I'M HAVING A HASH-LISTIC
EXPERIENCE.
AND HAVIN' AN OMELET
MEANS MAKIN' A CHOICE.
66 OMELETS?
SAUSAGE-HAM OMELET.
(man) PHILLY CHICKEN.
NUMBER TEN.
PEANUT BUTTER AND JELLY
AND BANANA?!
THE SMALL PLACE WITH
THE BIG BREAKFAST IN PHOENIX...
(Guy) THE ATMOSPHERE IS TINY
AND SQUISHED AND COMPACT.
BUT THAT'S WHAT'S
GREAT ABOUT IT.
WHERE THEY'RE DEAD SERIOUS
ABOUT COOKIN' FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S THE BEST BREAKFAST
IN TOWN.
IT FEELS MORE LIKE YOU'RE
EATING BREAKFAST AT HOME.
IS MY MOM HERE?
AND THE JERSEY JOINT
WHERE THE PANCAKES
JUST KEEP ON COMIN'...
AND COMIN'...
AND COMIN'.
31 DIFFERENT KINDS
OF PANCAKES?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
NOW IF YOU BEEN WATCHIN'
"TRIPLE D," YOU KNOW THAT I AM
A CORNED BEEF HASH HOUND.
NOW WHEN I FIND A HOUSE
OF CORNED BEEF HASH,
ISN'T IT FITTING THAT IT'S
CALLED MAMA'S 39th STREET DINER?
'CAUSE FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
COMIN' HERE IS LIKE COMIN' HOME.
HOW ARE YA?
MAMA IS JAN IMBER.
SHE'S EVERYBODY'S MAMA.
AND SHE TREATS YA JUST LIKE
YOU'RE HER KIDS, TOO,
SO YOU'LL GET, "HEY!"
SHE IS A TRUE MAMA.
JAN'S HUSBAND IRA AUERBACH
IS ON THE GRILL.
THE CORNED BEEF
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
I'M HAVING A HASH-LISTIC
EXPERIENCE.
TWO OVER-EASY ON THAT,
OR WHAT?
AND IT'S NOT
JUST THE HASH.
ANYTHING THAT YOU CHOOSE IS--
IS GREAT.
IT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S GOOD
STUFF, BRO.
THERE'S DEEP-FRIED
FRENCH TOAST...
CRISPY TEXTURE, AND INSIDE
IT'S NICE AND GOOEY.
A PANCAKE AND SAUSAGE THING
CALLED A ROLLED OINK,
MORE THAN 60
DIFFERENT OMELETS...
IF I TRIED TO LOOK AT THAT LIST,
IT WOULD TAKE ME ALL DAY.
AND THE MENU GOES ON AND ON.
I'M HAVIN' THE COAL MINER.
YOU GOT SAUSAGE. YOU GOT GRAVY.
YOU GOT EGGS ON TOP.
THE HANGOVER SCRAMBLER--
CHILI, ONIONS,
SCRAMBLED EGGS
AND HASH BROWNS.
A BREAKFAST BAGEL "SAMICH."
YUM.
ON-POINT HOME COOKIN'
FROM A COUPLE OF TOTAL
FOOD FANATICS...
HI, BABY.
NOW FEEDING A GOOD PART
OF KANSAS CITY.
AND HERE'S YOUR
CORNED BEEF HASH.
WE MET THROUGH FRIENDS,
AND OUR FIRST CONVERSATION
WAS THERE'S NO DECENT
KAISER ROLLS IN THIS TOWN.
THEY ENDED UP MARRYING.
THEN NINE YEARS AGO...
WE WANTED
TO FEED PEOPLE.
THEY OPENED UP WHAT'S BECOME
A LOT OF FOLKS' FAVORITE JOINT.
CAN YOU TELL HIM WHAT KIND
OF PANCAKES YOU HAVE?
I HAVE A CHOCOLATE
CHIP PANCAKE!
(Guy) AND IS HE THE COOK
IN THE FAMILY?
(Jan) YES, HE IS NOW.
WE DON'T STEP ON HIS EGO.
(laughs)
I GREW UP IN
A DELICATESSEN FAMILY.
WHERE CORNED BEEF WAS AN ART,
SO IRA'S HASH STARTS WITH
A FRESH CORNED BEEF BRISKET
AND A WHOLE LOT
OF PICKLING SPICE.
OH, IT SMELLS NICE.
SO YOUR GUY BRINGS YOU THESE
BRINED AND PICKLED
TO YOUR SPECS.
RIGHT.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
NOW WHAT HAPPENS IS I'M GONNA
POUR THE BEER OVER 'EM.
NOW JUST FOR GOOD MEASURE,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE MORE
OF THE PICKLING SPICE.
MUSTARD SEED
AND JUNIPER BERRIES.
UH, A LITTLE CORIANDER,
SOME CLOVE--
THERE'S A NICE,
BIG CHUNK OF CLOVE.
SO HOW LONG DOES
THIS GO DOWN FOR?
350 FOR 4, 4 1/2 HOURS.
DEPENDING ON THE SIZE
OF THE BRISKET.
LET'S GO.
NOW WILL YOU PEEK AND LOOK?
UH, NEVER.
AND NO TIMERS?
NO TIMERS, MAN.
TIMERS NEVER WORK, MAN.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
IT COOKS THROUGH JUST
LIKE A NORMAL BRISKET,
AND THE GREAT THING ABOUT IT
IS THE HOPS IN THE BEER
ALSO ADD AS A TENDERIZER
TO IT.
OH, MY GOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT BABY.
HOLD ME.
SO THAT'S YOUR BRINE,
YOUR RUB SEASONING MIX.
RIGHT.
AND THE BEER.
THAT IS GREAT, MAN.
THANK YOU.
AND NOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA CHOP THAT UP
REALLY GOOD.
LOOK AT YOU!
HAI! HAI! HAI!
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD AT THIS.
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
NOW I'M GONNA TAKE SOME
PARTIALLY COOKED POTATO.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE
ONIONS--A LITTLE CHOPPED ONIONS.
THERE'S ONE OTHER
LITTLE TRICK.
THE JUICE THAT WE COOKED
THE BRISKET IN.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BRISKET JUICE.
NOW THE OTHER THING IS,
YOU'RE GONNA NOTICE,
I-I DON'T PUT--
ALL RIGHT.
OH, I LOVE THIS!
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
WHAT WE MADE TO A FLATTOP.
THAT'S A REGULAR ORDER?
THAT'S A REGULAR ORDER,
MY MAN.
I'M NOT DONE YET.
THEN I'M GONNA TAKE A LITTLE'
BIT OF FRIED POTATOES,
SO YOU'RE GONNA HIT 'EM
WITH A LITTLE CRUST ON ONE
SIDE THEN FLIP IT OVER HERE
WITH A LITTLE CRUST
ON THE OTHER SIDE?
RIGHT.
THAT'S AN ORDER, BABY.
OH...
CAN I JUST HAVE
A LITTLE PRIVACY, PLEASE?
OH, MAN.
THAT HAS GOT A CRUNCH
AND A SALTINESS
AND A TENDERNESS.
THAT'S HASH, BABY.
THIS IS HOLY HASH.
BUT AS GREAT AS THAT IS,
IF YOU FEEL LIKE AN OMELET...
NUMBER 59.
YOU GET A CHOICE HERE.
66 OMELETS?
66 OMELETS.
YOU'VE GOT A 35 OMELET.
IT'S A NUMBER,
NOT A NAME.
THIS IS THE NUMBER TEN.
I GET IT EVERY SINGLE WEEK.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE OMELET--
CORNED BEEF HASH.
OH, IS THAT
CORNED BEEF HASH?
CORNED BEEF HASH--
CORNED BEEF HASH AND SWISS.
OKAY, YOU GOT A 32 AND A 39.
32--
(together) HAM, ONION,
GREEN PEPPER, CHEDDAR AND JACK.
AND A 39 IS A...
39 IS A PHILLY STEAK.
PHILLY STEAK, GREEN PEPPER,
ONION AND SWISS.
PEANUT BUTTER AND JELLY
AND BANANA?!
THAT'S FOR THE PEOPLE WHO THINK
ELVIS WAS JUST HERE YESTERDAY.
CHEDDAR, BROCCOLI, CHEDDAR,
ONION, SAUSAGE, TOMATO--
PHILLY-CHICKEN OMELET
WITH AVOCADO.
COUNTRY-FRI--COUNTRY-FRIED
STEAK AND ONION
SMOTHERED IN GRAVY OMELET?
ABSOLUTELY.
IRA'S GOT THAT KIND OF TWIST
FOR ALMOST EVERYTHING HERE.
OKAY, THIS IS NOW REALLY
GOING INTO A WEIRD REALM.
IF YOU WANT SAUSAGE
AND PANCAKES,
HAVE A ROLLED OINK...
WHOA. WHOA.
OR FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S DEEP-FRIED,
AND ANYTHING DEEP-FRIED
IS PRETTY AWESOME.
(laughs)
YOU DEEP FRY
THE FRENCH TOAST?
ABSOLUTELY. DEEP FRY IT.
(moans)
THIS IS BETTER THAN ANY
FRENCH TOAST I'VE EVER EATEN.
THAT'S GETTIN' YOUR FRIED
FREAK ON RIGHT THERE, MAN.
THAT'S IT.
AND IF THE FRENCH TOAST
ISN'T SWEET ENOUGH FOR YOU...
LOOKS LIKE A GIGANTIC
SUGAR BURRITO.
IT IS.
IRA'S DEEP FRYING
HIS CINNAMON ROLLS, TOO.
(Guy) PLEASE TELL ME
THAT WE'RE GONNA
SPRINKLE IT WITH SOME POWDERED
SUGAR WHEN IT COMES OUT.
OF COURSE.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
GET ME A FORK.
WOW.
THAT CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THAT...
AND COME LUNCHTIME...
OKAY, YOU'VE GOT
AN "OH, MY GAWD BURGER"
"G-A-W-D"
OH, MY GAWD!
OH, MY GAWD.
20 OUNCES OF MEAT.
WOW.
THAT'S SOME GOOD MEAT.
THAT IS JUICY. KNOW
WHAT I WOULD LIKE ON THAT?
WHAT'S THAT?
CORNED BEEF. HUH?
OKAY, MAYBE NOT ON THE BURGER,
BUT GET A LOAD OF THIS HUNK
OF IRISH CORNED BEEF.
WITH FRESH TURKEY,
CHEESE AND HOMEMADE SLAW,
IT'S SOMETHIN' CALLED
A JERSEY JOE.
(moaning)
STUFF STICKS TO YA.
IT'S GOOD.
AND THE CUSTOMERS
STICK TO MAMA'S.
IT'S PROBABLY 60% TO 70%
OF OUR BUSINESS
IS PEOPLE WE SEE
FIVE DAYS A WEEK.
EVERYTHING IS
SO WELCOMING HERE.
JUST ONE PROBLEM...
OKAY, GUYS, LET'S GO.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T GET IN HERE
ON A SATURDAY OR SUNDAY MORNING.
WE GOTTA HAVE A PLACE
TO PUT ALL OUR FRIENDS.
NOW THEY FOUND ONE.
WHEN WE WERE THERE,
JAN AND IRA WERE GETTING READY
TO MOVE DOWN THE STREET...
WOW, YOU WENT
VEGAS, BABY.
TO A PLACE
ALMOST THREE TIMES AS BIG.
MAKES MY KNEES WEAK.
BUT IT'LL STILL BE MAMA'S.
IT'S THE PLACE TO GO.
YOU DON'T NEED TO BE FANCY.
YOU JUST NEED TO BE GOOD.
DON'T TRY TO GRAB SOMETHING
OUT OF THAT SWEET BOOTH
WITHOUT TALKIN' TO HER FIRST.
AND MAMA WILL STILL
BE IN CHARGE.
I'M GONNA STICK MY FINGER
IN EVERY CAKE THAT COMES BY.
DON'T GET--
DON'T GET CAUGHT.
SHE'S EVERYBODY'S MAMA.
EVERYBODY'S MAMA.
COMIN' UP...
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
WE'RE HEADIN' TO PHOENIX
TO MEET A CAT NAMED MATT.
BREAKFAST ISN'T
REALLY COMPLICATED.
KEEP IT FRESH.
COOK IT TO ORDER.
AND THE SIGN SAYS IT ALL.
DO YOU REALLY
TASTE ANY OF IT?
'CAUSE IT LOOKS LIKE MOST
OF IT'S ALL THE WAY OUT HERE.
WHEN YOU'RE IN DOWNTOWN
PHOENIX, ARIZONA,
YOU JUST GOTTA CHECK OUT
THIS LITTLE JOINT
CALLED MATT'S BIG BREAKFAST.
NOW THIS DUDE
DIGS BREAKFAST SO MUCH
HE DEVOTED AN ENTIRE
RESTAURANT TO IT.
I JUST GOTTA MEET THIS CAT MATT.
YOU DON'T BECOME
AN EGG GENERAL THAT EASY.
I'M SO EXCITED!
THE HANDS ARE FLYIN'.
WHO'S HAVIN' THE BREAKFAST
SPECIAL TODAY?
IT'S SO GOOD.
EGGS AND PORK CHOP
IS VERY GOOD.
(Guy) THE ATMOSPHERE IS TINY
AND SQUISHED AND COMPACT.
THAT'S WHAT'S
GREAT ABOUT IT.
CHRIS, PARTY OF ONE?
IT'S THE BEST BREAKFAST
IN TOWN, HANDS-DOWN.
IT FEELS MORE LIKE YOU'RE
EATING BREAKFAST AT HOME.
IS MY MOM HERE?
(man) I WOULD SAY
THE SPECIALTY
IS QUALITY.
IT'S NOT YOUR
REGULAR BREAKFAST.
IT'S BREAKFAST BASICS DONE
THE RIGHT WAY...
IT'S SQUEEZED
A LOT OF ORANGES.
TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH...
(Matt) BREAKFAST ISN'T REALLY
COMPLICATED. KEEP IT FRESH.
MADE WITH THE BEST INGREDIENTS.
THE BACON HERE
IS SO THICK AND PEPPERY.
WE DON'T EVEN OWN A FREEZER.
WE DON'T OWN A MICROWAVE.
WE DECIDED--
THERE'S NO MICROWAVE
AND NO FREEZER IN THIS JOINT?
NO MICROWAVE,
NO FREEZER, NOPE.
WAFFLE?
WAFFLE'S PERFECT.
THEY'RE REALLY LIGHT,
VERY DELICATE.
'CAUSE MAKIN' 'EM MATT POOL'S
WAY MEANS MAKIN' FRESH BATTER
THREE TIMES A DAY.
YOU WANT TO HELP ME CRACK,
OR SHOULD I JUST DO IT ALL?
WELL, I'VE NEVER CRACKED
IN TANDEM BEFORE.
AND JAZZ HANDS!
WE GOT 2 CUPS
OF SUGAR HERE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME BUTTER
IN THERE--PUT IT IN MELTED.
NOW YOU'RE NOT WORRIED ABOUT
KINDA POACHIN' THOSE EGGS
A LITTLE BIT
WITH THAT HOT BUTTER?
WE'D WORRY IF I
DIDN'T START WHISKIN'.
OKAY.
THE FLOUR AND THE WHOLE MILK,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD THEM
IN ALTERNATE DOSES HERE.
WHAA! WHAA!!
CAREFUL.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY!
WE DO HAVE
A MIXER HERE, RIGHT?
NO, NO, NO.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY MIXER.
WE DON'T HAVE ROOM FOR A MIXER.
THEN WE ADD
THE, UH, BAKING POWDER.
IT'S JUST A TEASPOON OF SALT.
JUST LIKE CAKE BATTER.
THAT'S IT RIGHT THERE.
PUT THAT DOWN.
GIVE IT A FLIP, AND IT
ONLY TAKES ABOUT A MINUTE.
SO YOU FLIP IT BACK OVER.
IT'S LIKE A HIKING BOOT
JUST WALKED ON A PANCAKE.
LOOK AT THAT THING!
THAT'S A HOT FRISBEE OF FUN.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT.
GRANNY'S KETTLE
ON THE FLATTOP ALL DAY
IS ACTUALLY HOT SYRUP?
IT'S HOT SYRUP
READY TO GO.
YOU DON'T WANT TO PUT COLD
SYRUP ON A HOT WAFFLE.
THAT'D KIND OF RUIN IT.
IT'S GOT A CRU--
A REALLY NICE CRUST TO IT.
LOOK AT THAT
INSIDE THERE.
YOU SEE HOW NICE AND LIGHT
AND AIRY.
REALLY GOOD. I'D EAT THAT
WAFFLE AGAIN IN A HEARTBEAT.
I GOTTA TELL YA, MAN,
YOU COULD CONVERT
NON-BREAKFAST-ERS.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
NON-BREAKFAST-ENERS?
ACTUALLY...
HOME FRIES
OR HASH BROWNS?
HE ALREADY HAS.
NOW WHAT WILL
THE WAIT TURN INTO, LIKE,
ON AN AVERAGE WEEKDAY
OR WEEKEND?
HOUR AND A HALF.
TO GET IN?
OH, YEAH, IT'S WORTH
THE WAIT FOR SURE.
(hostess) I'M GONNA TAKE GREGORY
PARTY OF TWO, PLEASE.
GREGORY!
WE DROVE ALL THE WAY
FROM NORTH SCOTTSDALE
TO HAVE BREAKFAST HERE.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE
ABOUT IT HERE?
HMM...
MY DADDY OWNS IT.
I STILL REMEMBER, YOU KNOW,
GOIN' TO A LITTLE COFFEE SHOP.
MY DAD LOVED COFFEE SHOPS.
HE ALWAYS SAT
AT THE COUNTER.
I JUST FIGURED THERE WERE PEOPLE
HERE THAT WOULD APPRECIATE
JUST OLD-FASHIONED,
MOM-AND-POP RUN RESTAURANTS.
SO THREE YEARS AGO,
HE AND HIS WIFE ERENIA...
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
GOT A COUNTER OF THEIR OWN.
I'M HERE
ALMOST EVERY OTHER DAY.
IT FILLED UP QUICK.
WELCOME TO PHOENIX.
HOW ARE YOU, MAYOR?
DO YOU ENJOY THE SAME THING
EACH TIME YOU COME IN?
NO, I LIKE THE WAFFLES
OR THE OMELETS.
THE WAFFLES
WITH THE REAL MAPLE SYRUP.
AND IT'S THAT REAL THING THAT'S
KEEPIN' THIS JOINT PACKED.
EVERY PIECE OF MY BREAKFAST
IS SO GOOD.
WE GET ALL OF OUR PORK FROM
A LITTLE LOCAL BUTCHER SHOP.
THEY DON'T DELIVER,
AND I PAY RETAIL.
IT'S THE CRAZIEST THING
IN THE WORLD.
ONCE YOU HAVE
THE BACON HERE,
YOU'LL NEVER EAT BACON
ANYWHERE ELSE YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
THIS IS LIKE WINE
TASTING FOR ME.
I'M GONNA CLEANSE
MY PALATE WITH THE BACON.
IT'S AS THICK AS A HAM STEAK.
GREAT TEXTURE TO IT.
WHOLE GRAIN BREAD--YOU KNOW THAT
THEY MAKE THIS STUFF SLICED?
I DON'T LIKE
UNIFORMITY OF BREAD.
THE MAN HAS AN ISSUE
WITH UNIFORMITY OF BREAD.
AND THEN WE SERVE IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF HOMEMADE LOCAL PRESERVES.
MMM!
IT'S LIKE AN OPEN-FACED
JELLY DOUGHNUT.
MOST OF IT'S
ALL THE WAY OUT HERE.
THERE YOU GO.
AND MATT'S PUTTIN' FRESH
ROSEMARY IN HIS HOME FRIES...
KIND OF MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
COOKED IN TONS OF BUTTER,
JUST LIKE THE HASH BROWNS.
WE BUTTER THE GRILL.
WE LAY OUT THE HASH BROWNS.
WE BUTTER IT ON TOP.
AND THEN WE JUST
KEEP FLIPPIN' 'EM.
OH! THOSE ARE KILLER!
THE SALAMI SCRAMBLE
IS MADE WITH SOPRESSETA,
BROUGHT IN SPECIAL
FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
HE'S EVEN MAKIN' FRESH PESTO
FOR HIS BREAKFAST PORK CHOPS.
WE MAKE A PESTO MARINADE.
WE PUT THE, UH,
GARLIC IN THERE FIRST.
IT'S ABOUT 1 1/2 OUNCES
OF FRESH BASIL.
PINE NUTS.
MADE A RED BELL PEPPER
PESTO WITH MACADAMIA NUTS.
FOR PASTA, OR FOR...
UH, NO, JUST PUT A FACIAL.
I WEAR IT AS A MUD MASK
AT NIGHT.
THAT'S A SECRET.
GREAT.
SEA SALT, PEPPER, AND THEN
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
AND YOU JUST KINDA
DO THIS BY SIGHT.
LOOK AT THE COLOR IN THAT.
I'VE GOT SOME CHOPS HERE.
TOSS 'EM AROUND.
CAN I LICK THE BOWL, MAN?
ALL YOURS.
MONEY.
HOW LONG'S IT MARINATE?
AT LEAST THREE HOURS OR SO.
IT'S GONNA GET A NICE
LITTLE CRUST ON IT.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S
TIME TO FLIP.
THOSE BAD BOYS
GOTTA BE DONE.
YOU WANT TO GIVE 'EM A SHOT?
YOU CAN JUST SEE THE JUICE
COMING OUT OF IT.
AH! FANTASTIC. YOU KNOW,
YOU GET THE LITTLE PESTO,
GET SOME OF THE BITE
OF THE GARLIC--
I LOVE THAT YOU DO FRESH CRACKED
PEPPER. THAT'S MY BIGGEST THING.
THE FOOD HAS
A LOT OF LOVE IN IT,
AND YOU CAN ALWAYS TASTE IT
WHEN PEOPLE COOK WITH LOVE.
ALREADY PEOPLE
ARE STARTING TO DEVELOP
THAT SORT OF GENERATIONAL
THINKING WHERE THEY CAN
PICTURE THEIR KIDS COMING HERE
50 YEARS FROM NOW,
20 YEARS FROM NOW.
THE SPECIAL IS TODAY
CORNED BEEF HASH
WITH POACHED EGG.
THANK YOU.
WELCOME.
I WANT IT TO BE, LIKE,
A MIDWESTERN STYLE DINER.
WINDOW, PLEASE.
THANKFULLY,
PEOPLE RECOGNIZE IT.
WELL, THE FOOD'S ALWAYS GREAT.
YOU CAN TELL THAT WHOEVER MADE
THIS FOOD IS AN ARTIST.
THEY'RE THE SWEETEST PEOPLE.
JUST MAKE YOU FEEL
LIKE YOU'RE PART
OF THE FAMILY.
WELL, I APPRECIATE IT.
THANKS FOR COMIN' IN.
SO ON OUR NEXT STOP OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
WHERE YOU WANT TO GO?
HELP!
WHERE WE ARE GOING NEXT
IS NEW JERSEY...
KILLER BREAKFAST.
TO A JOINT WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
PANCAKES BY THE DOZEN.
YOU STILL GOT MORE TO GO.
YOU KNOW, YOU COULD
FIND AN AVERAGE PANCAKE
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE.
BUT FINDING
A REALLY KILLER PANCAKE--
WELL, THAT'S
A WHOLE NOTHER DEAL,
AND THAT'S WHY I'M
IN JERSEY CITY, NEW JERSEY,
AT THIS FAMILY-OWNED JOINT
THAT'S DOIN' 'EM RIGHT--
DOIN' 'EM RIGHT
31 DIFFERENT WAYS.
HONKY-TONK PANCAKES.
CRAN-APPLE PANCAKE.
MEAT PANCAKE.
(man) OH, MY GOODNESS.
BEAUTIFUL, GUYS.
NUTTY PANCAKES.
BERRY PANCAKES.
THAT'S A WINNER, WINNER
CHICKEN DINNER RIGHT THERE.
THEY'RE AWESOME.
THROW IN JUST ABOUT ANYTHING
ELSE YOU COULD ASK FOR...
THEY MAKE A KILLER BREAKFAST.
AND YOU'VE GOT
THE BROWNSTONE DINER,
A ONE-STOP BREAKFAST SHOP
THEY'RE LININ' UP FOR.
IT'S ALWAYS CROWDED.
AND WHOLE WHEAT TOAST.
EXACTLY.
LET'S ROCK.
IT'S A TRADITION THE BOURNIAS
FAMILY'S KEPT GOING
FOR MORE THAN 40 YEARS.
YOU GUYS READY?
FOLLOW ME.
THANK YOU.
THE FIRST GENERATION
CAME HERE FROM GREECE.
MY MOM CAME HERE WITH HER,
UM, FATHER AND SIBLINGS.
THERE YOU GO.
THE KIDS ALL STARTED OUT
IN DIFFERENT PROFESSIONS...
ALL RIGHT, DEBBIE!
BUT COULDN'T STAY AWAY.
WE ALL WANTED TO WORK
AS A FAMILY AGAIN.
I WANTED TO KEEP
THE TRADITION GOING.
I LOVE WORKING
WITH MY FAMILY.
I WOULDN'T' HAVE IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
NEITHER WOULD THE FOLKS
LINING UP
FOR THEIR KILLER PANCAKES.
NOW WHO DID
THIS RECIPE COME FROM?
IT'S MY FATHER'S.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE EVER SEEN
A 5-GALLON BUCKET OF BUTTERMILK.
VEGETABLE OIL?
YEP. YOU DO ANOTHER
GALLON OF EGGS.
GETS A LITTLE MESSY.
I'VE GOT TO SAY FLOUR
COMES IN AT SOME POINT.
WE JUST DO PRETTY MUCH
SIX CONTAINERS OF THIS.
YEAH, YOU KEEP
IT SCIENTIFIC.
THAT'S THREE.
THAT--THAT WAS FOUR.
HERE IS SIX.
OKAY, THAT'S GONNA BE SEVEN--
THIS'LL BE SEVEN.
AND THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
AND THAT'S--
I THINK YOU--
I THINK YOU OWE ONE MORE.
WE GOT ONE MORE TO GO?
(laughs)
YOU'RE THROWIN' OFF
MY COUNT.
(laughs)
WE JUST ADD A TOUCH
OF VANILLA SYRUP.
THE SECRET INGREDIENT'S
IN HERE.
YOU'RE HIDING IT
IN CONFECTIONARY SUGAR.
YEAH.
HOW LONG WILL
THE BATTER LAST?
FOR A DAY OR TWO?
OUR BATTERS ARE
ONLY FOR THAT DAY.
THIS SIZE--WE DO ABOUT 12
ON THE WEEKEND.
WHY DO THEY GIVE ME
THE EASY-BAKE SPATULA?
(man) THAT'S IT.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT.
BERRY, MEAT,
HONKY TONK.
GOT IT.
CAN WE MAKE THOSE?
YEAH, I'LL EVEN GIVE YOU
A NUT 'N' HONEY.
THAT'S ANOTHER
BIG FAVORITE, IF YOU'D LIKE.
NUT 'N' HONEY.
AND YOU SEE THE WAY THIS
BATTER'S NICE AND THICK?
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT
A NICE TEXTURE.
BEFORE WE PUT THE TOPPINGS,
I JUST WANT IT
TO COOK JUST A LITTLE BIT,
JUST TO KIND OF CREATE
THAT LITTLE CURL.
NOW THIS IS SPECIFICALLY
JUST THE PANCAKE STATION.
THERE IS NOTHING ON THIS GRILL
BUT PANCAKES.
IF YOU'RE GONNA CALL
YOURSELF PANCAKE FACTORY,
YOU BETTER HAVE
A PRECISION-LY TUNED...
GRILL, JUST FOR IT.
THAT'S IT.
GRIDDLE JUST FOR THIS.
THIS IS THE MEAT PANCAKE.
FRESH BACON, COOKED.
JUST THROW THAT RIGHT THERE.
THE NUT IS, UH, ALMONDS,
SOME WALNUTS.
THE HONEY GOES AT THE END.
FOR THE HONKY TONK, THESE ARE
PEANUT BUTTER. REALLY GOOD.
YOU SEE THE WAY IT'S
GETTIN' THAT NICE HEIGHT?
RIGHT. RIGHT.
NOW HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHICH ONE'S WHICH?
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO
TURN 'EM OVER.
NOW YOU WOULD
GET YOURS--
USUALLY ON AN ORDER, YOU WOULD
GET THREE NUTTY LIKE THAT?
YEAH.
NUTS AND HONEY.
JUST A LITTLE
POWDERED SUGAR.
JUST SHOVEL IT IN.
OH, I SHOVEL.
JUST SHOVEL.
IT'S MY MIDDLE NAME.
MMM. I WOULD ORDER
THAT PANCAKE.
HOW DOES THIS PANCAKE
STACK UP?
GET IT?
ACTUALLY, IT'S AWESOME.
THIS IS OUR HONKY TONK.
GOOD PEANUT BUTTER FLAVOR.
I LIKE THAT THE BANANA
GOES ON NOT HOT.
THEY'RE NICE. THEY'RE FLUFFY.
THEY'RE ALWAYS FRESH.
THIS ONE--
HOT STRAWBERRY PRESERVES.
AND WE JUST TAKE A DAB
OF SOUR CREAM.
WHOA!
GOT, LIKE, THAT HOT/COLD--
THAT IS LIKE ADULT WARM
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE.
YOU STILL GOT MORE TO GO.
(whistles)
OH, THIS IS THE MEAT PANCAKE.
EXCUSE ME?
CAN I GET SOME, UH,
KETCHUP AND HOT SAUCE?
ON THE PANCAKE?
THAT'S GOOD, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN'
ABOUT RIGHT THERE!
THE LOCALS HAVE BEEN TALKIN'
ABOUT THESE PANCAKES
AND A WHOLE LOT MORE...
FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
FOR MORE THAN 40 YEARS.
BROWNSTONE DELUXE.
EAT THE ONION RINGS FIRST
AND THEN THE BURGER.
BUT WITH THIS MENU, YOU'RE
NEVER TOO FAR FROM A PANCAKE.
IT'S THE COUNTRY
PANCAKE WRAP.
IT'S LIKE
AN OVERSIZED PANCAKE
AND WE WRAP
DIFFERENT STUFF IN IT.
LIKE PIGS IN THE BLANKET
GONE WILD?
YEAH.
GOT SOME EGGS, POTATOES,
SAUSAGE, SOME CHEESE.
IT'S GOOD.
CALLED A PANCAKE BURRITO--
PANCAKE GYRO.
THAT'S GOOD, YOU SAID "YOU-RO."
A LOT OF PEOPLE SAY "JI-RO."
BUT GYRO, THAT'S, UH...
IT'S NOT MY FIRST
PANCAKE RODEO.
WOW. LOOK AT
THAT PROFILE.
YOU GOT THAT SWEET
AND SALTY AND THE EGG.
MMM.
ALL THE FLAVOR
INSIDE THE PANCAKE.
I'M TELLIN' YA,
SAVORY PANCAKES.
(man) THEY HAVE A LOT OF
DIFFERENT PANCAKE WRAPS HERE.
IT WORKS, THOUGH.
IT TASTES REALLY GOOD.
CAN I MAKE ONE.
YEAH.
PANCAKE WRAP
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA STYLE.
MY PARENTS ENCOURAGED ME
TO PLAY WITH MY FOOD.
(as Scotty from "Star Trek")
IT'S BREAKIN' APART, CAPTAIN!
(normal voice) OH, THERE YOU GO.
HOW ABOUT ANY BLUE CHEESE?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
WOW.
YOU PUT ON
SPICY BUFFALO PANCAKE
ON THAT MENU,
THERE'S SOMEONE GONNA TRY IT.
OH, MAN,
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
I HAVEN'T COME HERE YET AND HAD
ANYTHING THAT I DIDN'T LIKE.
WE JUST LOVE IT.
IT'S REALLY GREAT.
I USUALLY HANG OUT HERE
ALL DAY.
UP NEXT...
YOU GUYS SURE LIKE
TO SPLASH AROUND HERE.
DAD'S JUMPIN' IN
WITH SOME GREEK HOME COOKIN'
HE GREW UP WITH.
(Guy) THIS IS THE MANSION
OF MOUSSAKA.
AT THE BROWNSTONE DINER
IN JERSEY CITY, NEW JERSEY...
(Bobby) OKAY, PICKUP.
THEY CALL THEMSELVES
THE PANCAKE FACTORY.
31 DIFFERENT KINDS
OF PANCAKES.
YEAH, THAT'S ABOUT RIGHT.
I WAKE UP ON SATURDAY MORNING,
AND THIS IS WHAT I THINK ABOUT.
THE BOURNIAS FAMILY'S
BEEN DOIN' IT
THIS WAY FOR DECADES.
MY DAD WOULD SEE PEOPLE PULL UP,
AND HE'D START MAKING
THEIR PANCAKES 'CAUSE HE KNEW
WHAT THEY WERE GONNA GET
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
BUT DAD'S ALSO
FAMOUS AROUND HERE
FOR COOKIN' UP THE FAMILY
FAVORITES HE GREW UP WITH
BACK IN GREECE.
THE MOUSSAKA
IS VERY AUTHENTIC.
DELICIOUS.
SO WHAT DO WE DO FIRST?
UH, SAUTé THE ONIONS.
WHAT ELSE WE GOT IN HERE?
WE GOT SOME DILL.
PARSLEY.
ITALIAN PARSLEY,
FLAT-LEAF. OKAY.
PUT A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
I LIKE YOUR
MEASURING TECHNIQUE.
A LITTLE BIT
OF WHITE WINE?
YEAH.
BUT WHY IS IT IN THE GLASS
I'VE BEEN SEEING YOU
YOU DRINK OUT OF
ALL MORNING?
THAT'S WHAT I DO ALL DAY.
OKAY, I LIKE IT.
PUT IN THE GROUND BEEF NOW.
THE DICED TOMATOES.
YEAH, PUT A LITTLE
BIT FLOUR.
TOMATO PASTE.
LOOKS GOOD.
YOU PUT IN THE POTATOES.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN THE POTATOES.
THAT SPLASHING OIL DOESN'T
BOTHER YOU, DOES IT?
NO.
SHALL WE CUT SOME EGGPLANT?
WHAT TEMPERATURE, 350?
YEAH.
FOR...
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
20 MINUTES.
AND LAYER IT ALL UP
LIKE A GREEK LASAGNA.
POTATOES IN WITH EGGPLANT.
OH, NICE AND CRISPY.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS LOOKIN', BOSS.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
AND A SCRATCH-MADE
BéCHAMEL SAUCE.
STILL DO IT.
OKAY, I'LL STILL DO IT.
THAT'S PUT IN THE OVEN NOW.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT ONE HOUR.
ALL RIGHT!
LOOK AT IT.
OKAY, GUY.
IS THIS FOR TWO?
NO, IT'S FOR ONE.
MMM.
CREAMY. IT'S RICH.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
CREAM SAUCE ON TOP.
LIKE A BéCHAMEL.
REALLY NICE.
I SEE WHY IT'S SO POPULAR.
AND I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST
A PANCAKE FACTORY.
NOT THAT THERE'S ANYTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
THE PANCAKES ARE REALLY THICK
AND, LIKE, CAKE-LIKE.
IT'S AWESOME.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT I GET
BREAKFAST 24 HOURS A DAY.
YEAH, I JUST
LOVE THE PLACE.
IS THIS WHAT Y'ALL
THOUGHT THE DINER BUSINESS
WAS GONNA BE?
UH, WE ANTICIPATED
THE LONG HOURS,
BUT, UH, IT'S
A LOT OF FUN.
HEY, LOUIS!
AND THEN I JUST SCREAM ALL DAY,
SO IT WORKS OUT PRETTY WELL.
I HAVE A LOT OF FUN.
YOU'RE GONNA COME
TO WORK TOMORROW?
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU.
IT'D BE NICE IF MY DAD HAD,
LIKE, A DOZEN KIDS
THIS WAY WE COULD SPLIT
THE SHIFTS A LITTLE BIT EASIER.
SHOULDA HAD MORE KIDS.
(Guy) SHOULDA HAD MORE KIDS?!
WE'VE GONE TO PANCAKES
TO WRAPS.
AND LOOK--THERE'S
SO MANY MORE CHAPTERS.
BUT THAT IS ALL
FOR THIS READING TODAY
AS THE BROWNSTONE TURNS.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
BY THE WAY, LET ME
HELP YOU WITH THIS.
DID I GET THESE RIGHT?
I LIKE THE SHADES,
BUT THEY GO LIKE THIS.
LET ME HELP YOU HERE.
I GOTTA--
I MEAN, IF WE'RE GONNA
DO THIS--THERE WE GO.
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S HOW YOU ROLL 'EM OUT.
ALL RIGHT.