HI. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU GOTTA HAVE A BITE.
REGIONAL FAVORITES...
THIS IS CONSIDERED A VEGGIE?
MY KIND OF VEGGIE.
IN SPRINGFIELD, ILLINOIS...
LOOK AT THAT--HOT-A.
CUT IT UP
AND HOPE FOR THE BEST.
WHERE THIS IS A SANDWICH...
GOT A BREAKFAST SHOE.
CALLED THE HORSESHOE.
THERE'S NO REASON YOU
SHOULD LEAVE HERE HUNGRY.
AND I'M INVENTING
ONE OF MY OWN.
(Guy) WELL, YOU GOTTA GET
ALL THREE POTATOES ON THERE.
WE'RE HEADING TO VIRGINIA
TO A PLACE
THAT'S BEEN
SOUTHERN-COOKIN' FOREVER...
THIS IS
THE COLLARD GREENS.
(man) PORK CHOPS.
CHICKEN'S
A BIG THING HERE.
AND PEANUTS
ARE A FOOD GROUP...
HEY, PEANUT PIE, PLEASE.
AND TO NEW MEXICO...
(man) THAT LOOKS LIKE
A HOT TUB IN FLAVOR TOWN.
WHERE IT'S ALL ABOUT CHILI.
THEY HAVE
THE BEST GREEN CHILI HERE.
I LIKE THE RED HERE A LOT.
THIS IS ART.
OH, IT'S DELICIOUS.
THEY'RE DOING IT EVERY WAY
IN EVERYTHING.
I THINK IT'S ACTUALLY
THE OFFICIAL STATE QUESTION.
HOW DO YOU WANT YOUR CHILI,
RED OR GREEN?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO NOW I'M GONNA TAKE YOU
TO A JOINT
THAT WAS AN AIRPLANE HANGAR
IN WORLD WAR II.
THEN IT BECAME A TOWN HALL,
WELL, THEN A PLUMBING SHOP,
AND, OF COURSE, IT EVOLVED
INTO A RESTAURANT.
DID I MENTION
IT'S A QUONSET HUT?
EATIN' GOOD FOOD
IN A QUONSET HUT?
WELL, WORKS FOR ME.
QUONSET HUTS WERE
THE BIG SILVER BUILDINGS
THE ARMY PUT UP
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
IN THE '40s AND '50s.
HALF A CENTURY LATER,
IN SPRINGFIELD, ILLINOIS,
THIS ONE'S STILL STANDING
AS CHARLIE PARKER'S DINER.
ROBIN, SMALL PANCAKE.
DID YOU BUY THE BUILDING?
YES.
GIRLS, ORDER.
(woman) MY HUSBAND AND I
HAD COME IN HERE
WHEN IT WAS
A RESTAURANT PREVIOUSLY.
HE SAID, "YOU KNOW, I THINK
WE CAN DO BETTER THAN THIS."
HASH BROWN.
AND I SAID, "YOU KNOW,
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT."
AND MY REUBEN BASKET
AND SMALL CAKE.
SO WHEN THE RESTAURANT
BECAME AVAILABLE,
BRENDA SHIRLEY AND HER HUSBAND
MADE AN OFFER.
YOU HAVE WHAT EXPERIENCE
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS?
NONE.
JUST A DREAM...
I LOVE TO COOK.
AND THEY MADE IT WORK...
HOT SAUCE
OR ANYTHING, BOYS?
CRANKIN' OUT BIG PLATES
LIKE THE REUBEN SANDWICH,
HOMEMADE STUFFED PORK CHOPS,
OVERSTUFFED OMELETS
AND A LOCAL SPECIALTY
YOU CAN ONLY FIND AROUND HERE
THAT A FRIEND OF MINE TOLD ME
I JUST GOTTA TRY...
"T-RAY"--THOMAS RAY,
ONE OF MY FRATERNITY BROTHERS.
AND HE SAID,
"YOU KNOW WHAT?
ON
'DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,'
YOU GOTTA TRY
THE HORSESHOE."
THE HORSESHOE--
A HUGE COMBINATION
OF JUST ABOUT ANYTHING
YOU CAN PILE UP
ON A COUPLE PIECES OF BREAD.
IT'S JUST A HIT IN CENTRAL
ILLINOIS. IT'S JUST GREAT.
DOES THAT LOOK
THE RIGHT SIZE?
SURE.
GOOD CHEESE SAUCE
IS HARD TO FIND.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
GIDDYAP.
THE SHOE WAS INVENTED HERE
IN SPRINGFIELD...
YOUR SHOE COMIN' UP.
BACK IN THE '20s.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(man) TWO PIECES OF TOAST,
A PIECE OF HAM ON IT,
AND THE HAM IS CUT
IN A HORSESHOE SHAPE
AND THEN A CHEESE SAUCE.
THE FRENCH FRIES
WERE TO PUT ON TOP
AS THE NAILS
IN THE HORSESHOE.
WOW!
A HAMBURGER SHOE.
CHEESE SAUCE.
SOME OTHER FOLKS
WILL TELL YOU
THE FIRST SHOE WAS ACTUALLY
MADE WITH HAMBURGERS.
THERE YOU GO, GIRLS.
BUT THESE DAYS, THEY'LL MAKE IT
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
I PREFER IT
WITH SAUSAGE GRAVY.
BREAKFAST SHOE OVER EASY.
EGGS OVER EASY
AND THE HASH BROWNS.
THE BREAKFAST SHOE--THEY ALL
GET TWO PIECES OF TOAST.
(Guy) WITH SCRAMBLED.
NOW HE'S GONNA ADD
THE EGGS.
THAT'S A MESS.
LOOK AT THAT!
OKAY, THERE'S THE FOUNDATION
OF OUR HORSESHOE.
"BACON."
LOOK AT THAT!
THERE'S NO REASON YOU
SHOULD LEAVE HERE HUNGRY
WITH SOMETHIN' LIKE THIS.
NO, SIRREE.
"HALF CHEESE,
HALF GRAVY."
OH, IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND THE AMERICAN FRIES.
THERE, YOU GOT
ONE BREAKFAST SHOE.
DO YOU HAVE A SCALE?
JUST THE FOOD ALONE
IS 3 POUNDS.
SO THIS IS READY
FOR THE WINDOW?
THAT'S READY
FOR THE WINDOW.
THEY'LL CRANK OUT MORE THAN
3,500 BREAKFAST SHOES A YEAR.
A THOUSAND
DIFFERENT VARIATIONS.
THEY WANT IT
ON WHOLE WHEAT.
(man) HASH BROWNS,
WHEAT TOAST--
THAT MAKES IT HEALTHY,
YOU KNOW.
SAUSAGE PATTIES,
EGGS OVER EASY, GRAVY...
EGGS OVER EASY
AND THE HASH BROWNS.
YOU CAN HAVE
HALF AND HALF.
YOU HAVE ONE FRIED EGG
AND ONE POACHED EGG?
SAUSAGE AND GRAVY,
SCRAMBLED EGGS...
ONE PIECE OF RYE,
ONE PIECE OF WHOLE WHEAT.
AND I'M NOT GONNA HAVE TO EAT
ANYTHING THE REST OF THE DAY.
BUT THERE'S ALL
THOSE LUNCHTIME SHOES, TOO.
I'M WAITIN'
ON MY HAMBURGER SHOE.
CHICKEN, STEAK...
BREADED TENDERLOIN SHOE?
YEAH.
YOU CAN GET FISH.
PEOPLE REALLY GET IT
WITH FISH?
WITH FISH.
WHATEVER THEY GET IT WITH,
THE HEAVY HITTER
FOR THE LUNCHTIME SHOES
IS BRENDA'S
HOMEMADE CHEESE SAUCE.
IT'S BRENDA'S
SECRET RECIPE.
(Guy) WHOSE RECIPE?
MY MOTHER'S.
SO WHAT DO WE DO? OH, WE GET
SOME FLOUR THAT GOES DOWN?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A ROUX.
YOU GOTTA KEEP MOVIN' IT,
OR YOU'LL RUIN IT.
ROUX-IN IT.
YOU WANT
A NICE CREAMY ROUX.
NOW WHAT?
OKAY, ADD OUR MILK.
ADD JUST A LITTLE BIT
AT FIRST, RIGHT?
YES.
CHEESE...
NICE AND CREAMY.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
WE HAVE A SPECIAL SEASONING
THAT WE ADD.
OKAY.
I CAN'T GIVE YOU
THE SECRET
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT MAKES
OUR CHEESE SAUCE.
YES!
WHOO-HOO!
IT'S HOT.
LITTLE BITEY.
YEAH. THAT'S GOOD, THOUGH.
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE REALLY DIG.
MM-HMM.
AND IT'S NOT JUST THE SHOES
THAT ARE BIG HERE.
YOU GONNA BE ABLE
TO FINISH?
EVERYTHING'S BIG...
(Guy) LOOK AT
THAT HOT HAM.
LIKE A HOT HAM AND CHEESE
SANDWICH CALLED A SLIM JIM,
STUFFED PORK CHOPS AND A GERMAN
SPECIALTY CALLED ROULADIN
FROM BRENDA'S MOM'S RECIPE.
IT'S A STEAK, AND IT'S ROLLED
WITH GARLIC, ONIONS.
(Guy) THERE'S A LITTLE BACON
IN THERE.
YOU KNOW,
RIGHT OUT OF THE OVEN.
YOUR MOM WASN'T
DOING YOU WRONG ON THAT.
AND GET A LOAD
OF THE PANCAKES.
THAT'S A BIG PANCAKE.
16-INCH PANCAKE.
(Guy) 16-INCH?
DID YOU KNOW WHAT YOU
WERE GETTIN' INTO?
I DIDN'T.
THAT'LL MAKE 'EM PROUD!
NOW HOW MANY OUNCES OF BATTER
DO WE PUT DOWN
FOR THE MONDO CAKE?
ABOUT 18 OUNCES.
WHICH IS BIGGER,
THE PANCAKE OR MY HEAD?
THAT'S WAY TOO MUCH.
YOU GET 4 OF 'EM FOR $8.
YOU EAT IT ALL, WE BUY IT.
IT GOT THE BEST OF ME.
IT DID?
YEAH.
BUT IN THIS BIG HUT
OF BIG PLATES...
YOU CAN EAT THAT,
CAN'T YOU?
OH, YEAH.
THE KING OF THE HILL
IS STILL THE SHOE.
PROBABLY EAT HALF OF IT.
I CUT IT UP
AND HOPE FOR THE BEST.
I CAN EAT 'EM FOR BREAKFAST,
LUNCH AND SUPPER.
YOU GOTTA MAKE A SPECIAL SHOE
FOR A BUDDY.
OKAY.
I DON'T THINK BREAD BY ITSELF
REALLY SAYS ENOUGH.
I DON'T THINK IT SAYS,
"I LOVE YOU."
LET'S MAKE ONE
OF THOSE BIG PANCAKES.
HAM STEAK,
BURGER PATTY...
HOW EXACTLY WILL WE
BE MOVING THIS?
YOU ACTUALLY HAVE
A PIZZA PEEL?
A PIZZA PEEL.
SLIDE IT UNDER QUICK
SO IT DON'T STICK.
THERE YOU ARE.
WHOA!
VERY NICE.
THAT'S A BIG 'UN.
A HAM, A PATTY.
DO YOU WANT EGGS ON THIS?
HOW ABOUT THREE SCRAMBLED?
THREE SCRAMBLED?
VERY NICE!
WHAT DO WE SERVE THIS ON,
A TRASH CAN LID?
WE GOT A PIZZA TRAY.
WOW! THAT'S HOT!
SAUSAGE AND BACON TEMPLE.
OH, YEAH.
YOU GOTTA FIT
THE PALATE THERE, YES.
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
THERE WE GO.
BECAUSE THIS SIDE IS MORE
OF THE LUNCHY SIDE OF IT.
RIGHT.
JUST HIT THAT
WITH SOME OF THAT.
OH! HO-O-O-T!
WE GOTTA GET
ALL THREE POTATOES ON THERE.
HE IS SO GONNA THANK ME.
I DON'T LIKE TO SHAKE OFF
ANY OF THE EXCESS OIL.
THROW THAT ON THERE.
I THINK
IT LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
YOU THINK WE SHOULD
JUST GO FOR IT?
GO FOR IT.
WOW!
(laughs)
HOLY COW!
THIS IS
THE WHOLE HORSESHOE SANDWICH.
HAPPY HORSESHOEING.
YES.
THAT SHOULD AT LEAST
COVER YOU TILL LUNCH.
I'LL STILL BE
EATIN' IT AT LUNCH.
IT'S BEEN TWO HOURS.
HOW ARE YOU?
COME ON,
LOOSEN THAT SHIRT UP!
(laughs)
GET IN THERE, SON!
UP NEXT...
MMM.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO VIRGINIA...
THIS IS GOOD
SOUTHERN HOME COOKIN'.
FOR THE KIND OF COOKIN' FOLKS
AROUND HERE GREW UP WITH...
THAT'S THE WHOLE PLANT
RIGHT THERE.
NEXT, ON "WILD SAFARI"...
IF YOU'RE HEADIN' TO THE BEACH
ON ROUTE 460 IN VIRGINIA,
YOU'LL SEE
SOME PRETTY AMAZING THINGS,
LIKE WHERE THE FIRST PEANUT CROP
WAS PLANTED IN AMERICA
AND RIGHT DOWN
THE STREET FROM THERE,
ANOTHER PIECE OF HISTORY--
THE VIRGINIA DINER,
SERVIN' UP ALL KINDS
OF SOUTHERN FAVORITES
SINCE 1929...
HEY, PEANUT PIE, PLEASE.
THIS IS
THE COLLARD GREENS.
(man) PORK CHOPS.
GOTTA GET SOME BISCUITS.
HUSH PUPPIES,
COLE SLAW...
STEWED TOMATO, CHICKEN--
CHICKEN'S A BIG THING HERE.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU GOTTA HAVE A BITE.
THIS IS GOOD
SOUTHERN HOME COOKIN'.
THE WAY THEY'VE BEEN
DOING IT HERE SINCE 1929,
WHEN THE PLACE WAS A RAILCAR
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROAD.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE
WITH US.
OWNER BILL GALLOWAY BOUGHT IT
IN THE '70s.
I NEED
A SOUP BOWL, PLEASE.
GENERAL MANAGER MIKE STENNETT
SIGNED ON FIVE YEARS AGO...
TABLE 40 ON.
COMMITTED TO GIVING FOLKS
THE SOUTHERN COOKIN'
THEY GREW UP LOVIN'...
EVERYTHING
YOU'D EVER WANT.
LIKE THE FRIED CHICKEN,
HAM BISCUITS
AND PORK CHOPS
AND ESPECIALLY
THESE CLASSIC SOUTHERN SIDES,
LIKE CANDIED YAMS,
BLACK-EYED PEAS
WITH STEWED TOMATOES
AND THAT SOUTHERN STAPLE--
COLLARD GREENS.
THERE ARE A LOT
OF OTHER GREENS,
BUT COLLARDS IS THE GREEN
OF CHOICE IN THIS AREA.
IS THE GREEN OF CHOICE.
AND THIS IS HOW IT GROWS,
OR IS THIS A HAT?
THAT'S HOW IT GROWS.
THAT'S THE WHOLE PLANT
RIGHT THERE.
IS IT A TREE?
NEXT, ON "WILD SAFARI"..
EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL?
EVERYBODY'S IN.
THIS IS ALL
GONNA FIT IN HERE?
ALL GONNA FIT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE OTHER ONE IN THERE, TOO?
RIGHT.
WE PUT BUTTER, SUGAR...
SUGAR?
AND THEN WE HAVE
OUR HAM SKINS.
SO YOU GET YOUR SALT
OUT OF THERE.
YOU GET FAT OUT OF THERE.
YOU GET SOME
OF THAT SMOKED FLAVOR.
SO JUST FILL THE POT
IS THE BASIC IDEA.
FILL THE POT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME WATER.
FIELD TRIP.
THREE HOURS, YOU'LL
HAVE SOMETHIN' REALLY GOOD.
NICE AND TENDER.
MMM.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE HAM COMIN' THROUGH.
OF THAT FAT.
I THINK ANYBODY THAT THINKS
THEY DON'T LIKE COLLARD GREENS
MAYBE JUST HASN'T
HAD 'EM THE RIGHT WAY.
THESE MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE GREENS ARE GROWN LOCALLY
IN SEASON,
AND THE HAM COMES
FROM A SMOKEHOUSE
ABOUT 25 MINUTES AWAY.
OH, HO HO!
WE SERVE A HAM DINNER
WITH IT.
WE DO BAKED HAM SANDWICHES
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
WHAT WE SERVE THE MOST OF
IS OUR HAM BISCUITS.
PUT THE HAM IN THERE
WHILE THE BISCUIT IS HOT.
MMM.
THE HAM KIND OF
MELTS INTO IT.
YES, SIR.
AND IF YOU'LL NOTICE--
THIS COULD BE THE ONLY THING
YOU'D HAVE ON THE MENU,
I'D MOVE HERE.
MAN CAN SURVIVE ON HAM BISCUITS
ALONE, I THINK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE HAM IS NOT TOO SALTY.
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
BISCUIT ITSELF'S
GOT A NICE TEXTURE.
IT'S NICE AND FLAVORFUL.
'CAUSE THEY'RE
SCRATCH-BAKED EVERY DAY...
WHOA.
WITH BUTTERMILK.
YEAH, THAT ADDS
SOME CHUGALUG.
ABOUT THREE,
FOUR HANDFULS OF LARD.
YEAH.
MADE THE SOME WAY...
NICE AND PLIABLE.
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
WELL, LET ME
JUMP IN ON THIS,
'CAUSE YOU'VE BEEN
HAVIN' ALL THE FUN.
DO YOU LIKE BACON?
I LIKE BACON A LOT.
I LIKE HAM, BACON, SAUSAGE.
ANY OF THE PORK PRODUCTS,
I'M A BIG FAN OF.
I LIKE
TO HAVE GOOD BISCUITS.
AND THEN PUNCH 'EM OUT?
THERE YOU GO.
YEP, MINE LOOK THINNER.
THESE ARE THE PETITE--
I'M GONNA PUT THIS
IN HERE,
JUST SO THAT WE CAN
TELL THE DIFFERENCE.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT
A DENT IN MINE?
HEY, LOOK AT THAT. WHAT'S THAT
OVER THERE ON THE WALL?
YOURS ARE
LIKE KING KONG BISCUITS,
AND MINE ARE PETITE FLOWERS.
GUESS WHICH BISCUITS
I MADE?
(laughs)
THEY POINTED IT
RIGHT OUT, TOO.
IT SHOWS, DOESN'T IT?
WOW, LOOK
AT THOSE BISCUITS!
(laughs)
NO REASON--
LOOK AT 'EM. THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
DON'T! DON'T UNVEIL
MY LITTLE MINI BISCUITS.
THERE'S NOTHIN' WRONG
WITH 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS HOT, FLAKY.
WHOO!
MM-HMM.
I UNDERSTAND EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
YOU SPEAK BISCUIT-ESE?
I LOVE BISCUIT-ESE.
IT'S SOUTHERN-STYLE.
SOUTHERN-STYLE--
VERSUS NEW YORK-STYLE?
ACTUALLY, IT'S ALL
VIRGINIA DINER-STYLE.
I'M DELIGHTED
WITH MY PEANUT PIE.
YOU HEARD HIM--PEANUT PIE
RIGHT HERE IN PEANUT COUNTRY.
IT'S A CROSS
BETWEEN PEANUT BUTTER COOKIE,
PEANUT BRITTLE
AND PIE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S GOOD. EAT SOME.
I LIKE THAT.
AND THIS IS ONE
OF THE FEW PLACES
YOU CAN STILL GET CLASSICS
LIKE SPOON BREAD,
LIKE A SOFT, FLUFFY CORNBREAD
JUST A LITTLE FIRMER
THAN PUDDING.
IT'S SOMETHING MY MOM
AND GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE,
AND I REALLY DON'T,
SO IT'S A TREAT.
SAME WITH THE MAC & CHEESE--
A RIGHTEOUS RECIPE
WITH NO CORNERS CUT.
WE START WITH THE BUTTER
AND FLOUR
TO MAKE A ROUX.
REAL CHEDDAR AND AMERICAN?
RIGHT.
JUST WING 'EM IN AS FAST
AS YOU WANT TO WING 'EM.
WHOO! WHOO-HOO!
TAKE THE SHREDDED CHEDDAR
AND MIX IT IN WITH THAT.
NOW WHY DO WE PUT IT
INSIDE LIKE THAT
AND NOT INTO THE SAUCE?
IT MAKES IT HOLD
TOGETHER BETTER, I THINK,
WHEN YOU BAKE IT OFF.
CHEESE SAUCE IN.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW HOT
THAT STUFF IS.
NOW MIX HER UP?
MIX HER UP.
SO THIS BAKES
ABOUT 20 MINUTES?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
NOW YOU PULL IT OUT...
PULL IT OUT.
AND SPRINKLE IT?
SPRINKLE IT WITH CHEESE.
I CAN SEE--
OH, YOU DON'T--
YOU DUMP AND POUR.
I SPRINKLE.
PLENTY OF CHEESE.
NOW DOES IT GO
BACK IN THE OVEN?
GOES BACK IN THE OVEN
FOR A COUPLE MINUTES.
JUST TO LET THAT ALL MELT--
MAKES A NICE LITTLE CRUST?
RIGHT.
MAC & MOUNDS OF CHEESE--
PROBABLY UP THERE WITH SOME
OF THE CHEESIEST MAC & CHEESE
I'VE EVER HAD.
REAL NICE CHEDDAR FLAVOR...
UP ON TOP.
HOW MUCH DOES THAT COST?
OH, IT COMES
WITH YOUR MEAL.
ORDER AN ENTREE,
YOU GET TWO VEGGIES WITH IT.
THIS IS CONSIDERED
A VEGGIE?
OH, YEAH.
MY KIND OF VEGGIE.
IT TASTES LIKE COMFORT FOOD YOUR
MOM MADE WHEN YOU WERE LITTLE.
PUT THE TLC INTO IT,
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
THIS IS IT, YEAH.
WE CAME IN HERE WITH A DESIRE
TO MAKE IT HAPPEN.
Y'ALL, ENJOY YOUR LUNCH.
(Bill) THE GREATEST FUN I GET
IS SEEING THE PEOPLE.
IT MAKES YOU FEEL GOOD.
WELL, I'M DELIGHTED
TO HAVE YOU HERE TODAY.
MY FRIEND,
YOU MADE IT HAPPEN.
(laughs)
NEXT STOP...
A TOSTADA COMPUESTA.
NEW MEXICO, WHERE THERE'S
ONLY ONE QUESTION--
DO YOU WANT RED CHILI OR GREEN?
GET THE RED AND THE GREEN,
AND JUST SAY "CHRISTMAS."
I'M HERE
IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO,
AND WHY?
WELL, 'CAUSE I LOVE CHILIES.
I LIKE 'EM CHOPPED, DRIED,
FRESH, STEEPED, YOU NAME IT.
MEXICAN FOOD, ITALIAN FOOD,
CHINESE FOOD--
ANY WAY I CAN GET IT.
SO HERE I AM
ON MY GREAT CHILI QUEST,
AND I'M IN THE BACK KITCHEN
OF A SMOKIN' SOUTHWESTERN JOINT
CALLED TECOLOTE.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE CHILI.
I CRAVE IT AND NEED IT.
THEY HAVE
THE BEST GREEN CHILI HERE.
I LIKE THE RED HERE A LOT.
THIS IS ART.
WELL, IT'S DELICIOUS.
(Guy) THAT LOOKS LIKE A HOT TUB
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S WHERE
THE LOCALS EAT.
(man) THIS IS THE PLACE
TO COME DRINK COFFEE.
OWN IT.
YEAH.
BILL JENNISON'S A RESTAURANT
VET FROM BACK EAST...
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
WHO MOVED HERE AND FELL IN LOVE
WITH NEW MEXICO COOKING.
(Guy) SO HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN IN BUSINESS NOW?
(Bill) 27 YEARS,
AND WE'RE GONNA KEEP GOING
TILL WE GET IT RIGHT.
JUDGING BY THE CROWDS,
HE'S FIGURED IT OUT.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS JUST GREAT.
HE'S CRANKED OUT
ALL THE LOCAL FLAVORS.
...THAT YOU ONLY GET HERE
IN SANTA FE, AND IT'S FABULOUS.
THE MOST SPECIAL PART
IS THIS GREEN CHILI.
(Bill) GREEN CHILI COMES OUT
OF SOUTHERN NEW MEXICO,
OUT OF THE HATCH VALLEY--
ONE FARM,
GUY GROWS HIS OWN CHILI.
THAT'S THE ONLY ONE
THEY'LL USE HERE
FOR THEIR GREEN CHILI SAUCE,
MADE GALLONS AT A TIME
BY GENERAL MANAGER CHRIS VALDEZ
AND HIS CREW.
I'M GONNA TRY TO GO
FOR THE BACK OF THE POT.
AY!
LOOKS LIKE KERMIT THE FROG
SNEEZED ON ME.
IT'S PART OF THE JOB.
YOU KNOW, "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DRY CLEANING."
(laughs)
SO YOU BRING THE OAR IN...
AND THEN THE ROUX GOES IN--
ALREADY FEEL IT TIGHTENING UP.
OH, YEAH.
NOW THE SALT?
YES.
SEE HOW I'M DOING IT
AND NOBODY'S GETTING DIRTY HERE?
OKAY, SO WE'RE ALL DONE. LET IT
SIMMER FOR ANOTHER 45 MINUTES?
YES, SIR.
I MEAN, I'M NOT READY
OR ANYTHING.
(laughs)
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
NICE AND SMOOTH.
NICE GREEN CHILI FLAVOR
OF JUST THE CHILI ITSELF.
THEN YOU GET
THAT BACK HEAT.
OH, YEAH.
STARTS TO COME FORWARD NOW
FROM THE BACK.
(laughs)
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
AND THEY'RE PUTTING
THAT GREEN CHILI SAUCE
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
THAT'S WILD.
A BREAKFAST BURRITO.
HUEVOS YUCATECOS.
HUEVOS YUCATECOS,
OR HUEVOS "YOU CAN LEAVE 'EM."
WELL...
FRY A COUPLE EGGS.
AND WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THE BANANA?
WHAT I DO IS I PUT IT
ON THE GRILL AND WE FRY IT.
FRIED CORN TORTILLA?
THEN I'M GONNA ADD
OUR BLACK BEAN,
A LITTLE BIT OF CARROTS
AND CELERY.
LET'S GET ABOUT A SPOONFUL
OF FETA CHEESE.
DON'T SEE FETA OFTEN
IN SOUTHWESTERN FOOD, DO YOU?
NOT REALLY.
THIS IS MORE OF A DISH
FROM THE YUCATAN.
ADD OUR TWO EGGS...
SOME OF THAT WONDERFUL GREEN
CHILI SAUCE WE PREPARED EARLIER.
YOU ADD ONE SLICE
OF SWISS CHEESE,
PUT THIS IN THE SALAMANDER.
PUT THIS UP IN
THE CHEESE MELTER? OKAY.
WE ADD OUR FRIED BANANAS.
TOP IT OFF WITH SOME
FRESHLY DICED PICO de GALLO.
AM I SUPPOSED TO GET A SLAB
OF BANANA ON THERE?
YOU SHOULD GET A BITE
OF EVERYTHING.
WOW.
AND THE GREEN CHILI SAUCE
IS OUTRAGEOUS.
THE BANANA--
THE CREAMINESS AND SWEETNESS
COUNTERACTING THE SPICE,
'CAUSE THAT GREEN CHILI SAUCE
IS HOT.
THE BANANAS
REALLY MAKE IT SPECIAL,
BECAUSE YOU GOTTA HAVE
THAT LITTLE SWEET BITE.
GREEN CHILI--
YOU KNOW, THAT'S THE SECRET.
(Guy) IT'S KIND OF
LIKE THE WHOLE THEME.
BUT THAT'S ONLY HALF THE STORY.
I THINK IT'S ACTUALLY
THE OFFICIAL STATE QUESTION.
HOW DO YOU WANT YOUR CHILI,
RED OR GREEN OR CHRISTMAS?
IF YOU WANT TO COME ACROSS
AS SAVVY,
GET THE RED AND THE GREEN
AND JUST SAY "CHRISTMAS."
I LOVE ALL KINDS OF CHILI,
BUT RED CHILI, ESPECIALLY.
RED CHILI SAUCE.
RED CHILI...
IT'S ACTUALLY
THE SAME PEPPER.
WHAT IT IS--YOU KEEP IT ON
THE VINE LONGER, IT TURNS RED.
SO WHAT WAS ONCE THE GREEN
THAT WE USED TO MAKE THIS...
MM-HMM.
IS NOW THIS.
YES.
DIG IT.
IT'S ON A DIFFERENT
FLAVOR PROFILE.
WELL, YEAH,
WHEN IT DRIES OUT.
ALL THE TOPS
ARE TAKEN OFF
BECAUSE THE STEM
ISN'T TOO TASTY.
EXACTLY.
WE TRY TO TAKE OUT AS MUCH
OF THE SEEDS AS POSSIBLE.
OKAY.
RECONSTITUTE 'EM
IN WARM WATER?
ABOUT 1/2 A TEASPOON
OF GARLIC.
A LITTLE SALT?
THAT'S IT.
(blender whirring)
(imitating blender whining)
THAT'S LIQUI-PEPPER.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS PUT THIS
ON THE STOVE AND SIMMER.
AND THEN TIGHTEN IT UP
WITH A LITTLE ROUX?
YES, EXACTLY.
AND THIS IS GONNA BE THE SAUCE
THAT ALSO GOES ON THE ADOVADA.
WHAT IS CARNE ADOVADA?
IT'S A RED CHILI
WITH PORK.
THAT WAS--I MEAN, THOSE ARE
BOTH OF MY MIDDLE NAMES.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO
IS GET THE PORK STARTED.
LITTLE BIT OF WATER...
THIS IS A 3/4-INCH CUBED PORK.
THIS IS A PORK LOIN
WITH A 1/2 CUP
OF CHILI PEQUIN,
WHICH IS A RED CHILI SEED.
THIS WOULD BE THE SEED
OUT OF THE PEPPER?
YES, YES.
OKAY.
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
CHOPPED GARLIC,
MEXICAN OREGANO...
MEXICAN OREGANO.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER?
CHILI POWDER...
SOME SALT AS WELL.
SOME SALT FROM THE WELL, OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT SAUCE.
CAN YOU GET THAT
BOTTLED TO-GO?
YOU ACTUALLY CAN.
WE DO QUARTS AND PINTS TO-GO.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT, LIKE,
GALLON AND TANKER TRUCK.
(whistles)
THAT'S, LIKE, SUPERMAN SPICY.
NOW HOW DO YOU LIKE IT?
ME? I LIKE IT JUST WITH
THE TORTILLA, JUST LIKE THAT.
NICE, REALLY ROUND HEAT...
A LOT OF PEPPER FLAVOR.
MM-HMM.
AND THE PORK IS TENDER.
IT'S ALL IN THE COOKING PROCESS.
LOW AND SLOW.
THAT IS REALLY WARM.
I MEAN, IT'S--
EVENTUALLY, IT DOES KICK IN.
IT EVENTUALLY DOES--
IT IS SERIOUSLY
TOO LEGIT TO QUIT, THOUGH.
THIS HAS GREAT HEAT,
SO IT'S NOT TOO HOT,
AT LEAST NOT FOR ME.
THIS IS MY SOUL FOOD.
IT'S KIND OF
A NEW MEXICO TREAT.
...BUT NOT THE ONLY ONE.
(Chris) YOU'RE TRYING TO GET ME,
AREN'T YOU?
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE DOING PANCAKES
WITH A NEW MEXICO TWIST.
HOW MANY PANCAKES DO YOU
HAVE ON, IS WHAT I WANT TO KNOW.
SINCE 1980, THE TECOLOTE CAFE
IN SANTA FE
HAS BEEN SERVING KILLER
NEW MEXICAN SPECIALTIES...
A TOSTADA COMPUESTA...
GREEN CHILI...
IT'S, BY FAR, MY FAVORITE
IN SANTA FE.
RED CHILI...
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR A LONG TIME
JUST FOR THE RED.
AND CHRISTMAS.
CHRISTMAS MEANS YOU'RE
GONNA GET RED CHILI ON IT,
BUT YOU'RE ALSO
GONNA GET GREEN CHILI ON IT.
EVEN THEIR HOMEMADE PANCAKES
ARE DONE THE NEW MEXICO WAY.
WHAT WE HAVE HERE IS OUR
ATOLE PIÑON BLUE CORN PANCAKES.
FLOUR--JUST REGULAR
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THERE YOU GO
MAKIN' A MESS AGAIN.
THIS IS
ORGANIC BLUE CORNMEAL.
DEFINITELY A COARSER TEXTURE.
1 CUP OF SUGAR...
BAKING POWDER, 'CAUSE
THAT'S THE LEAVENING AGENT.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
AS WELL.
AND THIS, YOU JUST
MIX IT RIGHT UP.
AND YOU GUYS
MAKE THIS EVERY DAY?
YES, EVERY MORNING.
IT GETS MADE EVERY MORNING.
THERE WE GO. THERE WE GO.
YAHTZEE!
OKAY.
THIS REQUIRES FIVE EGGS.
AND I HAVE NO GRIP,
BUT NOW I DO.
WE'LL ADD THE OIL.
THE MILK--WOULD YOU LIKE
TO ADD THAT IN?
YOU'RE TRYING TO GET ME,
AREN'T YOU?
YOU WANT TO WHISK IT
WHILE I DUMP IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU'RE A WHISKING MASTER.
YOU DON'T REALLY
WANT TO OVERMIX.
YOU WANT THERE
TO BE THE LUMPS IN THERE.
WANT TO BRING
THE VESSEL OVER?
PLEASE.
THERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
AH, RIGHT DOWN
LIKE WALL PASTE.
I LIKE IT. AND THE NAME
OF THIS PANCAKE AGAIN?
THE ATOLE PIÑON PANCAKE.
ATOLE IS BLUE CORN?
YES. IT'S ANOTHER NAME
FOR THE BLUE CORN.
PIÑON IS PINE NUTS?
YES.
AND HOTCAKE? WELL, IF YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT A HOTCAKE IS,
TURN IT OFF.
WAIT TILL THE BUBBLES
COME AROUND THE EDGES,
AND THEN WE'LL GIVE A FLIP?
ABSOLUTELY.
THERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT THAT--
PINE NUTS IN THERE.
I JUST HAPPEN
TO HAVE A FORK.
GO RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
IT HAS SOME REAL TEXTURE.
IT'S NOT JUST
LIGHT, FLUFFY NOTHING.
THEN YOU CHEW AND YOU BITE
INTO SOME OF THAT PINE NUT,
AND IT REALLY OPENS UP
A BUNCH OF FLAVOR.
IF YOU LOVE PANCAKES,
THIS WOULD BE ONE OF THE BEST.
GREAT PANCAKES, GREAT EGGS,
GREAT CHILI...
DONE THE NEW MEXICO WAY...
SIT DOWN, FOLKS,
AND ENJOY YOURSELVES.
LIKE EVERYTHING HERE...
IT'S JUST EXCELLENT FOOD
AND GOOD PEOPLE.
FOR MORE THAN 27 YEARS.
IT'S FRIENDLY. EVERYBODY KNOWS
YOU WHEN YOU COME HERE.
THE SERVICE IS REALLY GOOD.
THE PEOPLE ARE REALLY FRIENDLY.
THEIR FOOD
IS ALWAYS SPECTACULAR.
(Guy) LET ME SEE A BIG BITE...
(gulps)
IT'S A SANTA FE EXPERIENCE,
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS IT.
WHAT A SMILE.
WELL, THIS IS GOOD FOOD
TO SMILE ABOUT.
IT'S A NICE FEELING GETTING
OUT OF BED IN THE MORNING
AND WANTING TO COME TO WORK.
YOU KNOW, IT'S THAT SIMPLE.
YOU STILL LOVE IT.
I DO.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HO-O-O-T!
IT'S LIKE LAVA,
ISN'T IT?
(neighs)
(neighing)