HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
57, YOUR DELICIOUS FOOD
IS READY.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WOW.
REAL-DEAL FAST FOOD...
INDESCRIBABLY DELICIOUS.
IT'S AMAZING.
(man) YOU CAN'T COMPARE
IT TO FAST FOOD,
BECAUSE IT'S JUST
SO MUCH BETTER.
A WHOLE LOT MORE
THAN BURGERS IN A BAG.
ORDER UP!
PANINI IN ALABAMA...
THAT'S SLAMMA-JAMMA
IN ALABAMA.
HOMEMADE AND HAND-MADE...
YOU KNOW IT'S FRESH.
EVEN THE MOZZARELLA...
YEAH! WE COULD PLAY
THIS GAME ALL DAY.
TEX-MEX IN A HURRY...
CLASSIC MEXICAN SPICES.
AND YOU GET IT FAST.
AT AN AUSTIN LANDMARK...
MADE THERE ON THE SPOT.
WHERE EVEN TORTILLAS
ARE MADE FROM SCRATCH...
MMM, THAT IS
REALLY GOOD.
AND FAST FOOD ON THE FARM
IN ARIZONA.
THERE IS NOTHIN'
LIKE FRESH FOOD.
DON'T FIND THAT
AT EVERY BURGER JOINT.
(man) NO, YOU DON'T.
I GOT A FONTINA BURGER
WITH STUFF
RIGHT OUT OF THE GARDEN.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
IT IS WHAT IT SAYS--
FARM-FRESH GRILL.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN YOU THINK FAST FOOD,
YOU THINK AMERICAN, RIGHT?
YOU KNOW, BURGERS, FRIES,
THE SPEAKER BOX,
THE WHOLE GIDDYAP,
BUT REALLY,
THERE'S FAST FOOD
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
AND HERE IN FAIRHOPE, ALABAMA,
THERE'S A GUY THAT'S DECIDED
TO DO HIS FAST FOOD
WITH A EUROPEAN SPIN.
YOU GOTTA MEET
"PANINI" PETE.
TURKEY, TUNA,
TWO MORE ROSEMARYS.
A CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF...
(Pete) HERE WE GO.
CRANKIN' OUT THOSE PRESSED
ITALIAN-STYLE SANDWICHES...
ORDER UP.
CALLED PANINIS.
WE'RE GONNA
PANINA-NIZE IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WOW.
IT'S NOT
AN ORDINARY SANDWICH.
YOU GOT TWO ROSEMARYS
CAME IN.
HE ROASTS HIS
OWN TURKEY
WITH HIS OWN SEASONINGS.
THIS IS THE STATE BIRD
OF FLAVOR TOWN, DUDE.
FRESH-CUT FRIES.
FRESH-CUT CHIPS.
IT'S AMAZING.
HE HAS HIS OWN
MOZZARELLA.
INDESCRIBABLY DELICIOUS.
AND FAST ENOUGH
FOR THE TIGHTEST LUNCHES.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN GET LUNCH AND EAT IT
AND BE BACK AT WORK.
ORDER UP!
IT'S FAST, AND YET...
IT'S NOT FAST FOOD.
(Guy) MM, THESE ARE GREAT-
LOOKIN' TOMATOES.
I HAVE A LADY THAT HAS A STAND
ON THE CORNER.
IT'S A SANDWICH JOINT,
BUT YOU GO AND GET
TOMATOES FROM DOWN--
YOU KNOW IT'S FRESH.
ALL DONE BY A CULINARY
INSTITUTE GRAD
WHO'S PROVING FAST FOOD
CAN STILL BE REAL FOOD.
(Pete) OUR DRESSINGS
ARE MADE FROM SCRATCH.
THE AIOLI.
YOU'RE MAKIN' YOUR OWN.
RIGHT.
WOW.
PETE'S A FIRST-CLASS CHEF.
WHO, AFTER WORKING FOR OTHERS
FOR 17 YEARS,
MOVED BACK TO ALABAMA...
HOW WE DOIN', GUYS?
AND TOOK A FAST-FOOD BAR
TOTALLY OVER THE TOP.
IT IS SO GOOD.
THIS IS THE RAW CURD.
CORRECT.
HE'S EVEN DOIN'
HIS OWN MOZZARELLA,
WITH FRESH CURD BROUGHT IN
FROM WISCONSIN.
YOU'RE CODDLING IT
GENTLY.
THE LESS MILK AND CREAM
YOU SQUEEZE OUT OF THERE,
THE CREAMIER THE FINAL
PRODUCT'S GONNA BE.
DO IT. DO IT!
YEAH!
YES!
WE COULD PLAY
THIS GAME ALL DAY.
(laughs)
NOW WE'RE GONNA
DO THE--
OH, MY GOD!
IS THAT--IS THAT GOOD,
OR WHAT?
HOLD ME.
ALMOST LIKE--LIKE BREAD DOUGH.
KINDA CRIMP IT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
LAY IT OUT HERE.
THE PLASTIC WRAP HELPS
KEEP IT IN A CONSISTENT--
OH, THAT PLASTIC WRAP.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT BEAUTY.
HOLD IT LIKE A LITTLE BABY.
(imitates baby crying)
AND THAT'LL HELP SET IT.
THAT'S GONNA HELP
TIGHTEN IT UP.
THAT'LL SET IT.
AW! SO IT'S NICE
AND WARM,
AND YOU CAN FEEL
HOW SILKY.
YOU'RE A NATURAL,
GUY.
THAT ROLLIN' THING'S A LOT
TOUGHER THAN YOU THINK.
THIS GUY'S REALLY GOOD.
LOOK AT THE SKILLS!
STACK IT WITH BASIL,
FRESH TOMATO,
AND A HOMEMADE
BALSAMIC VINAIGRETTE,
AND YOU'VE GOT ITALIAN
CAPRESE PANINI.
THE MOZZARELLA TOMATO.
AND GET THIS ONE
WITH MOTZ, RED PEPPER
AND TURKEY.
I GO WITH THE TURKEY
EVERY TIME.
YOU KNOW THE MOTZ IS FRESH.
THE PEPPERS ARE FRESH ROASTED,
AND SO'S THE TURKEY,
STARTING WITH PETE'S
SPECIAL HERB RUB.
LITTLE BIT OF ROSEMARY,
SAGE, SALT, PEPPER, GARLIC.
NOW WE GOTTA DO
THE LEMONS HERE.
I THINK WE'RE GOOD.
WOW, THAT'S NICE.
WHOO!
A CHEF LIKE YOU, I WOULD BE
THINKIN' BONE-IN FOR SURE.
WHEN YOU GET TO
THE METHOD, YOU'LL UNDERSTAND,
THE COOKING METHOD.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHY I OPENED UP MY MOUTH.
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW
TAUGHT ME THIS ONE.
TRIPLE WRAPPED--IT'S CALLED
AN "ALMOST FRIED" TURKEY.
THIS THING ABOUT YOU ROLLIN'
STUFF AROUND HERE...
THAT'S HOW WE ROLL.
THAT'S MY LINE!
AND THEN THIS.
NOW WHY FRY IT VERSUS BAKING?
SAME TEMPERATURE.
WELL, IT'S--
IT'S SHORTER COOK TIME.
IT'S REALLY CONVENIENT, AND IT
REALLY CREATES A GOOD PRODUCT.
YOU'LL SEE.
WANT TO SLICE SOME OF THIS UP,
TAKE IT FOR A RIDE?
LOOK AT THAT!
I'LL KEEP SLICING, 'CAUSE THAT'S
NOT GONNA BE ENOUGH FOR YA.
NO, THAT'S NOT.
WHAT A GREAT BLEND
OF THOSE SPICES.
THAT MIGHT BE THE MOST TENDER,
MOIST TURKEY I'VE EVER TRIED.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S
MAKE A SANDWICH.
WE START OFF WITH
A LITTLE FOCACCIA.
SO IT COMES
IN RAW DOUGH.
YES, SIR. DIJON--SOME OF OUR
HOMEMADE AIOLI ON TOP.
MOST PEOPLE WOULD JUST FANCY
UP A LITTLE MAYONNAISE.
GRAB SOME MAYONNAISE--
NO, SIR, NOT HERE.
SOME OF OUR TURKEY.
HEALTHY PORTION.
SOME ROASTED PEPPERS, LITTLE
PEPPER, FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
KOSHER SALT.
HIT IT WITH SOME BABY GREENS.
HOMEMADE BALSAMIC
VINAIGRETTE, MOZZARELLA--
REMEMBER YOUR BEST BUDDY?
OH, I SHOULD TRY THAT
BEFORE YOU PUT IT ON THERE.
YEAH, YOU BETTER TEST THAT.
LITTLE BUTTER AND OLIVE OIL,
JUST TO HELP KEEP
IT FROM STICKIN'
AND GIVE IT A NICE COLOR.
RIGHT IN THE BASKET.
YOU BETTER HOLD ONE FOR ME.
MMM.
I GOTTA TELL YA,
YOU START WITH THE BREAD--
NICE, LIGHT, GOOD CRUNCH--
MOVE RIGHT INTO
THAT MOZZARELLA,
THE GREENS--
THE BALSAMIC POPS.
EVERYTHING WORKS TOGETHER,
BUT NOTHING OVERPOWERS ANOTHER.
THAT'S SLAMMA-JAMMA
IN ALABAMA.
DUDE!
AND PETE'S PUTTING
JUST AS MUCH WORK
INTO SEVEN OR EIGHT DIFFERENT
KINDS OF PANINI EVERY DAY.
ORDER UP.
I GET DIFFERENT PANINIS
EVERY TIME I COME,
BUT THEY'RE
ALWAYS EXCELLENT.
THE TUNA'S AWESOME.
HERB-RUBBED
AND QUICK-SEARED.
ONE MORE ROAST BEEF.
IT'S HERB-RUBBED, TOO...
KIND OF MAKES IT SPICY.
THEN DONE AT HIGH HEAT
FOR JUST OVER TWO HOURS.
IT'S READY.
JUST FOR A SANDWICH.
ALL THAT WORK JUST FOR
A LITTLE SANDWICH.
WE NEED A PANINI BURGER.
YEAH, HE'S EVEN DOIN'
A BURGER THIS WAY,
AND A DOG ROLLED
IN A HOMEMADE CREPE.
AND IF YOU WANT
A DESSERT...
I'M HAVING THE BEIGNETS.
IT'S THE NEW ORLEANS
CLASSIC...
AMAZING.
DONE PANINI PETE'S WAY.
YUM-YUM.
THIS RECIPE'S KIND OF EVOLVED.
THIS IS WATER AND BUTTER.
IT'S A WET DOUGH PROCESS.
(Guy) TEASPOON
OF KOSHER SALT,
TABLESPOON OF SUGAR.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
DOZEN EGGS IN HERE.
TABLESPOONS OF VANILLA.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS ADD THE FLOUR INTO THAT,
AND YOU WANT TO GET THAT
NICE AND SMOOTH.
NO BAKING SODA,
BAKING POWDER?
NO, IT'LL BLOW UP
REAL NICE.
AND THEN WE'LL
TEMPER IN THE EGG.
'CAUSE IF YOU POURED
'EM ALL IN AT ONE TIME,
YOU'D GET YOURSELF
SCRAMBLED EGGS MIXED IN
WITH SOME SUGAR FLOUR.
WELL, YEAH.
NOW WE GET READY TO COME OVER
HERE AND COOK SOME.
HOW LONG'S IT TAKE ONE
TO COOK?
EIGHT MINUTES.
THE BEAUTIFUL THING ABOUT THESE
IS THEY KNOW JUST WHEN TO FLIP.
OH, THERE GOES ONE.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW WE GOTTA DO
THE RIGHT THING.
SECRET WEAPON RIGHT HERE.
LET'S PUT A LITTLE
LEMON SQUEEZE ON THERE
AND SEE WHAT WE GET.
LOOK AT THIS.
YEAH, BEAUTIFUL, HUH?
THEY'RE AMAZING.
THAT LEMON'S THE KEY.
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
KILLER.
IT'S KILLER.
PERFECT.
EVERYTHING'S AWESOME.
IT'S NOT LIKE
OTHER FAST FOOD.
QUAINT,
DELICIOUS.
FOOD'S REALLY FRESH.
THE PEOPLE ARE REALLY NICE.
ALL RIGHT,
Y'ALL ENJOY EVERYTHING.
FEELS LIKE IT'S REALLY
BEEN TENDERLY CARED FOR,
SPECIFICALLY FOR YOU.
(Pete) LABOR INTENSIVE,
BUT WHAT A DIFFERENCE
IT MAKES IN THE FOOD.
YOU KNOW, HE IS
THE PRICE OF PANINI.
(woman laughs)
OBVIOUSLY, YES, HE IS
VERY GOOD AT WHAT HE DOES.
ISN'T THAT RIGHT, PETE?
I AM THE PRINCE OF PANINI.
SAYS YOU.
SAYS ME.
COMIN' UP...
WHAT NUMBER, SWEETIE?
THIS IS REAL FOOD.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO AUSTIN...
IT'S A SOUTH AUSTIN
INSTITUTION.
FOR FAST FOOD TEXAS STYLE.
(Guy) WHAT DO YOU WANT
ME TO DO?
STIR IT, MIX IT AND
HAND YOU THINGS?
YEAH, YOU'RE A GOOD MAN.
SO THIS LEG OF OUR TRIP--
IT'S REAL-DEAL FAST FOOD
TEXAS STYLE.
SO HERE I AM IN AUSTIN
AT MARIA'S TACO Xpress,
AND YOU JUST GOTTA LOVE A JOINT
THAT WELCOMES YOU
WITH OPEN ARMS.
EVERYBODY'S ALWAYS
REALLY FRIENDLY.
ESPECIALLY MARIA.
HI, GIRLS.
SHE ALWAYS CALLS
YOU "SWEETIE."
WHAT NUMBER, SWEETIE?
MAKES YOU FEEL VERY WELCOME.
I LOVE THAT.
AND THE FOOD
IS AWESOME.
(woman) OH, MY GOODNESS.
REAL GOOD CORN TORTILLAS.
CLASSIC MEXICAN SPICES.
FANTASTIC.
AND YOU GET IT FAST.
OKAY, COME GET
YOUR FOOD.
MAN...
THESE ARE GOOD.
VEGETARIAN TACOS.
BEST TACOS IN AUSTIN.
MADE THERE ON THE SPOT.
(Maria) EVERYTHING
THAT YOU GET HERE
IS FRESH DAILY.
AND HAS BEEN
EVER SINCE MARIA CORBALAN
OPENED HER TACO Xpress
ALMOST 12 YEARS AGO.
IT'S A SOUTH AUSTIN INSTITUTION.
JUST LIKE MARIA...
57, COME GET YOUR TACOS.
THANK YOU.
AN ARGENTINEAN IMMIGRANT
WHOSE ONLY EXPERIENCE
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ...
(Maria) ANOTHER
ENCHILADA HERE.
AS WAITING TABLES.
AND I BOUGHT
A VERY LITTLE TRAILER.
I DIDN'T KNOW
HOW TO COOK.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
ALL THESE RECIPES?
I LEARNED THROUGH
MAKING MISTAKES, YOU KNOW.
"OH, I DON'T LIKE IT."
YOU COOK IT
AND THEN YOU ADD, AND--
THAT'S THE WAY
IT SHOULD NOT BE.
I GUESS IF YOU'RE NOT
REALLY HAPPY WITH IT,
JUST DESTROY IT.
AND NOW IT'S
TURNED INTO THIS.
THIS IS REAL FOOD.
YOU KNOW EVERYTHING
HERE IS FRESH
BECAUSE IT'S MADE--LIKE, YOU
CAN SEE THEM MAKING IT.
MORE THAN A DOZEN
DIFFERENT TACOS...
DELICIOUS.
HANDMADE ENCHILADAS...
(man) THAT IS AMAZING.
HOMEMADE REFRIED BEANS.
(woman) MMM.
THEY'RE EVEN MAKIN' TORTILLAS.
SO WE GOT OUR PRESS.
100% IRON.
IT'S CORN FLOUR.
ADD IN THE WATER.
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO
DO IT REAL HARD OR REAL FAST,
BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT
TO BE WEARING ALL THIS.
THIS THING IS STARTING TO LOOK
LIKE WE NEED IT TO LOOK.
JUST ENOUGH
TO HOLD IT TOGETHER,
BUT STILL FEEL LIKE
IT'S A LITTLE BIT DRY.
I PUT THE BALL
IN THE CENTER,
TAP IT WITH MY FINGERS,
AND THEN I APPLY THE FORCE.
GIVE IT THE FORCE MOVE.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
LOOK HOW BIG THAT IS.
AND SEE HOW UNEVEN
THE WHOLE THING IS?
THAT'S WHAT MAKES
IT HOMEY.
THIS IS ACTUALLY HOW THE FIRST
AIR HOCKEY GAME WAS INVENTED.
THAT WASN'T REALLY TRUE,
BUT IT SOUNDED COOL.
I CAN TELL THAT IT'S
A HOMEMADE TORTILLA
BECAUSE IT ABSORBS THE FLAVOR
MORE AND TASTES MORE FRESH.
AND THEY'RE USIN' 'EM
BY THE BUCKET LOAD.
CHICKEN ENCHILADA.
VEGETARIAN TACOS.
ENCHILADAS PICADILLO.
I LOVE PICADILLO.
WHEN THE OIL IS HOT,
WE JUST ADD THE MEAT.
YOU COOK THAT DOWN.
THEN THROW IN FRESH-CUT
CARROTS AND POTATOES,
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
CUMIN, SALT AND PEPPER.
EVERYTHING IS JUST
A LITTLE PINCH, OKAY?
CHIPOTLE PEPPERS.
SO THEY'RE DRIED, SMOKED
JALAPEÑO THAT'S RECONSTITUTED
IN AN ADOBO SAUCE.
THEN YOU BRING
THE ONIONS.
THE LAST THING IS
TO PUT THE TOMATOES.
SO YOU LET THIS SIT HERE
AND SIMMER LIKE THIS
FOR ABOUT, UH,
15 MINUTES?
YEAH, 15, 20,
25, AND--
15, 20, 25.
CAN I GET A 30?
GOTTA GET A 30.
GOT A 5. GOT A 35.
AND THIS WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN THE ENCHILADA?
YES.
BUT WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE ENCHILADA SAUCE.
YES.
SO THESE ARE GAUJILLOS,
AND WE'VE TAKEN OFF THE CAP.
YES.
AND THEY'VE GOTTA GET
A LITTLE BIT OF A BURN TO 'EM.
EXACTLY.
IN THE BLENDER, WE ADD
A LITTLE HOT WATER.
AAH!
THEN THIS IS TO GET THE SKINS
AND THE SEEDS OUT, RIGHT?
YEAH.
STARTING TO LOOK
VERY GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
ME TO DO?
STIR IT, MIX IT
AND HAND YOU THINGS?
YEAH, YOU'RE
A GOOD MAN.
LITTLE WATER.
LITTLE PEPPER, LITTLE GARLIC,
LITTLE SALT, LITTLE OREGANO,
LITTLE CUMIN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE ADD THAT IN THERE.
NOW THIS IS DONE?
YEP. BE CAREFUL.
OH...
GOOD?
THAT'S GREAT FLAVOR.
GRAB CORN TORTILLA,
DIP IT IN THERE.
WE GET DIRTY.
LOOK AT THAT.
OOH, YES.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA FRY THAT
SAUCE RIGHT ON THERE.
RIGHT, AND WHEN THE TORTILLA
START JUMPING,
IT'S TELLING ME
IT'S READY TO GO.
PUT THE PICADILLO IN THERE.
THERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT YOU ROLL
WITH TWO SPATULAS.
NOW WE PUT SOME
DELICIOUS CHEESE ON IT.
YOU GARNISH
WITH RICE, BEANS,
A LITTLE LETTUCE AND TOMATO
FOR THE COLOR.
THEN YOU'RE READY TO GO.
OH, THAT ENCHILADA SAUCE
IS DYNAMITE.
GREAT FLAVOR--
IT'S SWEET. IT'S SPICY.
THAT FRESH TORTILLA--
EVERYTHING HANDMADE.
FRYING THE TORTILLA
WITH THE ENCHILADA SAUCE
ON THE FLATTOP
MAKES THE DEAL.
HOWEVER YOU GET IT...
CHICKEN ENCHILADAS.
I'VE GOT CHICKEN.
ENCHILADAS
POLLO GUISADO.
GUISADO IS LIKE
A STEW.
THE CHICKEN INSIDE,
IT'S LIKE BARBEQUE-TASTING.
LIKE IT'S A LITTLE BIT SWEET,
BUT ALSO SPICY.
(Guy) LOOK AT THAT.
MAN, THE CHICKEN IS SO TENDER.
MELTED CHEESE.
THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
YOU CAN'T COMPARE
IT TO FAST FOOD,
'CAUSE IT'S JUST
SO MUCH BETTER.
BUT JUST AS FAST.
HOW MANY TACOS IN A DAY?
2,000, 3,000.
THIS IS FAST AND EXCELLENT.
(man) SO MUCH BETTER
THAN ANYTHING YOU CAN GET
THAT WOULD BE
CALLED FAST FOOD.
THE TACOS HERE
ARE HUGE.
MR. BOBBY, YOUR CRISPY
TACOS ARE READY.
THANK YOU.
THE GREATEST
BREAKFAST TACOS.
LIKE POTATO, CHEESE,
EGG AND BACON.
THE MIGAS TACO...
WITH TORTILLA CHIPS
RIGHT IN THE EGG.
ROCKS MY WORLD.
I'M HAVING TACOS
AL PASTOR.
I LOVE AL PASTOR.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS.
DICED UP PORK BUTT.
GUAJILLO SAUCE.
OPA!
WHOA! "YAHTZEE!"
PINEAPPLE,
A LITTLE CHOPPED ONION,
CUMIN, PEPPER,
OREGANO, GARLIC AND SALT.
NOW YOU PUT ALL
THAT STUFF OVER HERE.
HOW LONG WILL
THIS MARINATE?
I LIKE TO LEAVE
IT OVERNIGHT.
SMELLS GREAT.
WOW.
YOU WORK IT.
YOU WORK IT. YOU WORK IT.
SHALL WE THROW A COUPLE
FLOUR TORTILLAS ON?
YEAH.
WHOA.
PUT SOME ONIONS.
MMM.
CILANTRO.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE PINEAPPLE,
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
MMM.
FOR REAL, THESE WILL BE
GREAT WITH CHIMICHURRI.
YEP, SHE'LL EVEN TOP
A MEXICAN CLASSIC
WITH A HOT ARGENTINEAN
CHIMICHURRI SAUCE.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU, DARLING.
IT HAS A LOT OF REAL
GOOD DEPTH TO IT.
EXCELLENT.
IT'S A TREAT.
IT IS A TREAT.
BIG TREAT.
FANTASTIC.
ALL HAIL MARIA.
ONE PASTOR READY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL.
THIS IS ONE OF THE TEN REASONS
WE MOVED DOWN HERE.
NOT A REAL TRIP TO AUSTIN UNLESS
WE COME HERE AT LEAST ONCE.
OKAY, AND IS THIS
FOR HERE OR TO GO?
IT'S QUICK.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHEN YOU COME HERE,
YOU GET YOUR FOOD FAST,
BUT YOU DON'T LOSE
ANY QUALITY WITH IT.
I KNOW WHY YOU'RE
SO FAMOUS IN AUSTIN.
I GOTTA GET A CONDO HERE.
UP NEXT...
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?
IT'S A BURGER JOINT,
BUT IT'S SO NOT A BURGER JOINT.
FAST-FOOD BURGERS
THAT ARE NOTHING
LIKE FAST-FOOD BURGERS...
I GOT A BURGER WITH STUFF
RIGHT OUT OF THE GARDEN.
AT AN ARIZONA JOINT
THAT'S RIGHT ON THE FARM.
THE BEST-QUALITY INGREDIENTS
ARE THE ONES THAT ARE FRESH.
(Guy) ON THIS PART OF
THE REAL-DEAL FAST-FOOD TOUR,
WE'RE HEADED FOR THE FARM--
YOU KNOW, FRESH,
HOMEMADE INGREDIENTS.
SO WE HEARD ABOUT THIS JOINT
DOWN IN GILBERT, ARIZONA,
WHERE THEY'RE COOKING
WHAT THEY GROW.
I HAVE TO CHECK OUT
JOE'S FARM GRILL.
YEE-HAW!
WHAT CAN I
GET FOR YOU?
THERE'S NOTHIN'
LIKE FRESH FOOD.
YOU KNOW THAT IT'S JUST
COME OFF THE FARM.
(man) I'D LIKE
THE FARM BURGER.
(Guy) IT'S A BURGER JOINT,
BUT IT'S SO NOT
A BURGER JOINT.
WE WANTED TO
DO COMMON FOOD
REALLY, REALLY,
REALLY WELL.
IT IS WHAT IT SAYS--
FARM-FRESH GRILL.
YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
I LIKE TO KNOW
WHERE MY FOOD COMES FROM,
AND I KNOW WHO'S GROWIN' IT,
TOO, SO THAT'S KIND OF NICE.
THAT'D BE JOE JOHNSTON...
A LITTLE ICEBERG HERE.
WHOSE FAMILY'S BEEN
FARMING THIS LAND
SINCE THE EARLY '60s.
NICE.
THIS WAS ORIGINALLY
YOUR HOUSE.
IT WAS.
THAT WAS ORIGINALLY
YOUR FARM.
THE FARM IS 15 ACRES.
IT WAS 150.
WE KEPT 10% OF IT IN URBAN
ORGANIC FARMING.
GET A LITTLE RED ROMAINE.
THEY GET AS MUCH AS THEY CAN
FOR THE RESTAURANT
STRAIGHT FROM HERE.
(Joe) SERRANO CHILES COME
OFF THE FARM.
WHAT THEY HAVE TO BRING IN
FROM THE OUTSIDE
IS MOSTLY LOCAL,
ORGANIC OR NATURAL.
(man) CHICKEN'S READY!
I GOT A FONTINA BURGER
WITH STUFF RIGHT
OUT OF THE GARDEN.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
AND PUTTIN' ALL
THE GOOD STUFF TOGETHER--
KITCHEN MANAGER
CHAD BURNETT.
SO BURGERS ARE BIG?
HUGE.
WE USE 1/3 POUND
ALL ARIZONA BEEF.
BRAISED, BUTCHERED,
EVERYTHING FOR YOU GUYS.
PRESSED THIN
TO COOK QUICK...
CAN I HELP THE NEXT
IN LINE, PLEASE?
'CAUSE THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
1,400 A WEEK.
(Guy) SAUTEED MUSHROOMS--
NORMAL CONDIMENT BAR
YOU FIND AT ALL
FAST-FOOD JOINTS.
GRATED CHICKEN,
APPLE CIDER SMOKED BACON,
BLUE CHEESE.
OOH, LOOK, FRESH MOZZARELLA.
PEPPERONI
AND PESTO SAUCE.
MM-HMM.
YEAH, WE MAKE THIS HERE
WITH THE BASIL THAT WE, UH--
THAT YOU GROW, I KNOW.
YEAH. ROASTED PEPPERS.
THAT WE ALSO GROW.
RIGHT, AND THEN ARUGULA.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE
EVER HAD ARUGULA
THAT'S RIGHT OFF THE FARM,
BUT THIS IS GOING
TO BLOW YOUR MIND.
NICE, PEPPERY FLAVOR?
OH, IT'S INSANE.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT'S
A MAC DADDY PATTY.
MUSHROOMS--NICE, TENDER
BIG MUSHROOM FLAVOR.
THE ARUGULA.
BOY, THAT PATTY IS TENDER.
THAT'S EXCELLENT, MAN.
SO I DON'T KNOW,
GOURMET FAST FOOD?
LIKE GRILLED
PORTOBELLO MUSHROOM
WITH HOMEGROWN BEET SALAD
OR...
PERFECTLY GRILLED
AHI TUNA SANDWICH.
THE TUNA'S EXTREMELY FRESH.
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
A BURGER OUT OF THIS?
(laughs)
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A SUSHI-GRADE TUNA.
AHH!
AND THE ASIAN SLAW
ON THE TOP IS AMAZING.
YOU HAVE A LITTLE
SEASONING WE PUT ON IT
BEFORE WE POP IT
ON THE GRILL?
UH, YEAH, IT'S
A LITTLE ASIAN SEASONING.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE SEA SALT
WITH TOASTED SESAME SEEDS.
PRIMARILY WITH FISH,
I LIKE TO GO TO
TO THE HOTTEST PART OF
THE GRILL, SO IT'S JUST KINDA--
BAM! BAM!
SEAR, YOU KNOW?
THIS IS FAST FOOD
AT ITS FINEST.
DOCTOR IT UP, DOCTOR.
PUT A LITTLE
WASABI MAYO DOWN.
SOME JAPANESE HORSERADISH
AND SOME MAYONNAISE.
LEMON JUICE, AS WELL, FROM
PONDEROSA LEMONS OFF THE FARM.
THEN WE GOTTA GET
THE ASIAN SLAW GOIN'.
GOES WITH THE ASIAN SALAD
THAT GOES ON THE TUNA.
CORRECT.
START WITH THE CHILI PASTE
AND THEN THE LIME
TO KIND OF BREAK THAT
DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
SESAME SEED, CHOPPED MINT
AND CHOPPED BASIL.
ARE ALL THE HERBS
OUT OF THE GARDEN?
THEY ARE.
ABSOLUTELY.
WOW.
(Joe) MMM, THAT
SMELLS GOOD.
(Guy) DON'T FIND THAT
AT EVERY BURGER JOINT.
(Chad) NO, YOU DON'T.
CILANTRO. THE CHOPPED GINGER.
CORIANDER.
CHOPPED GARLIC.
YOU GROW GARLIC?
WE GROW GARLIC. YES, SIR.
AND THEN THE, UH, HONEY.
AND WE'RE WORKIN' ON
GETTIN' SOME BEES.
NO, BUT WOULDN'T THAT BE--
AND THEN, UH, SOME
TOASTED SESAME OIL
AND THEN THE PEANUT OIL
AND RICE WINE VINEGAR.
LOOKS DELICIOUS.
AGAIN, WHAT EXACTLY
YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND
AT A FAST-FOOD RESTAURANT.
YEAH.
SOME OF IT'S ALREADY HAD
A CHANCE TO SET UP.
SO WE'VE GOT SAVOY CABBAGE,
NAPA CABBAGE.
UH, NAPA CABBAGE
COMES OFF THE FARM.
BELL PEPPERS
COME OFF THE FARM.
GREEN ONIONS--
OFF THE FARM,
AND SOME MORE OF
YOUR FAVORITE--ASIAN SEASONING.
FRESH, HUH?
TELL ME YOU JUST DON'T MAKE
A SALAD OUT OF THAT BY ITSELF?
PEOPLE DO ORDER IT, THOUGH,
BY ITSELF AS A SIDE, ACTUALLY.
YEAH.
LET'S PULL IT.
OH, NOW THAT'S NICE AND RARE.
YES.
MY MOUTH SERIOUSLY
JUST STARTED TO WATER.
NOW I GUESS WE'LL, UH,
TOP IT WITH SOME SCALLIONS.
TAKE MY PICTURE WITH IT,
'CAUSE I WANT TO PUT IT
ON MY SCREEN SAVER.
DO YOU EAT IT BY HAND
OR WITH A SHOVEL?
(chuckles)
MMM, THAT'S OUT-OF-BOUNDS
AHI, MAN.
ALSO KNOWN AS
TERRIFIC TUNA.
WOW!
YOU GONNA SAVE ME A BITE?
NO, YOU WANT TO HAVE
SOME OF THIS?
GO AHEAD.
TAKE A BITE.
NOT MY FIRST RODEO.
SUPER-KILLER CRUNCHY
ASIAN SLAW.
MEAT'S SASHIMI.
"YEAH, SO I WAS DOWN
AT THE LOCAL BURGER JOINT..."
(laughs)
IF I EAT ANY MORE,
I'LL GO INTO A NAP.
IT TASTES VERY YUMMY.
IT'S NOT AT ALL
LIKE A TYPICAL BURGER.
(girl) WHAT CAN
I GET FOR YOU?
BUT NOTHIN'S TYPICAL HERE.
THIS IS THE WEDGE SALAD.
THEY GROW IT,
THEN GRILL IT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HOT DOG
WITH A PICKLE?
YEAH. I WENT THROUGH ABOUT
HALF OF IT. IT'S GREAT.
PICKLED FRESH
THREE OR FOUR TIMES A WEEK.
YOU CAN TELL
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
(woman) THESE ARE
THE SWEET POTATO FRIES
WITH PINEAPPLE SERRANO DIP.
UH-HUH.
OH, MAN.
IT'S NICE AND FRESH--
SOMETHING A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT AND UNEXPECTED.
EVEN THEIR ONION RINGS...
(Chad) PANKO.
IN JAPANESE-STYLE BREADCRUMBS
AND FRESH HERBS.
DILL COMES OUT
OF THE GARDEN, TOO?
OH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
THAT'S CAPITAL "K"
KRUNCHY. MMM!
I MEAN, THESE GOT, LIKE,
CRUNCH LIKE CEREAL.
NICE, CRISPY--
BEST I'VE HAD EVER.
THOSE ARE
TOO LEGIT TO QUIT.
AND WE'RE NOWHERE CLOSE
TO QUITTIN' TIME.
IT'S DEFINITELY
A FRESH-MADE PIZZA.
UP NEXT...
GRILLED BARBEQUE
CHICKEN PIZZA?
THEY'RE' PUTTIN' IT
ALL ON A PIZZA...
LOOKS TASTY.
(man) HAVE SOME.
WELL, I DON'T--
I MEAN--OF COURSE I WILL.
YEAH, NO, PLEASE, DON'T ASK
ME TWICE. WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
AT JOE'S FARM GRILL
IN GILBERT, ARIZONA...
(girl) YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
THEY'RE GROWIN' IT...
LET US HARVEST
SOME LETTUCE.
AND GRILLIN' IT.
(woman) GRILLED
WEDGED SALAD.
FONTINA BURGER
WITH STUFF RIGHT OUT
OF THE GARDEN.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S THE INGREDIENTS.
IT'S THE FARM FRESHNESS.
'CAUSE AT THIS JOINT...
THIS IS THE BARBEQUE
CHICKEN PIZZA.
THEY'VE GOT THEIR OWN TAKE
ON "OUTSIDE THE BOX."
WE GRILL PIZZA DOUGHS AT MY
RESTAURANT, JOHNNY GARLIC'S.
OH, YEAH?
I THOUGHT I WAS
THE ONLY ONE.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
THE SKIN ITSELF IS
ACTUALLY MADE BY OUR BAKER,
SAME GUY DOES OUR BREAD,
BUT WE SHEET IT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA MARK IT.
WE'RE GONNA WAIT FOR IT
TO KIND OF BUBBLE.
WHAT IS THIS TANNING BED
OF FOOD GOING ON?
THIS IS, UH--THEY'RE
CALLED CLAMSHELLS, AND, UH--
SO THAT'S WHAT
THE SUN FEELS LIKE.
WELL, THE DOUGH'S NOT DONE,
SO I ASSUME IT'S GOING
TO GO BACK ON?
OH, YEAH.
OUR CHEESE BLEND--
WHOLE MILK MOZZARELLA,
PECORINO, ROMANO,
AND IMPORTED FONTINA.
NICE.
FRESH MOZZARELLA.
OH, YEAH.
AND NICE BLUE CHEESE.
I THINK SOMEONE
WAS TYPIN' THIS UP
AND GOT STUCK ON THE WORD
SEARCH FOR "CHEESE"
AND JUST KEPT ADDIN'--
JUST KEPT GOIN'
AND GOIN' AND GOIN'.
GRILLED CHICKEN.
ALL HORMONE-, STEROID-FREE
CHICKEN OUT OF ARIZONA.
DICED RED ONION.
BEAUTIFUL TOMATOES.
AND THIS IS
THE CROWN JEWEL--
THE APPLE CIDER
SMOKED BACON.
PRACTICALLY A COB SALAD
ON TOP OF THE PIZZA SKIN.
AND THEN WE PUT OUR
JOE'S REAL BARBEQUE SAUCE.
PUT IT IN THE BACK
OF THE GRILL.
THEN THIS COMES DOWN.
THEN YOU BRING THE TURBO
COOKER 9000 ON TOP OF IT.
FIVE, FOUR.
PREPARE TO LAUNCH.
TWO, ONE.
(timer siren sounds)
(imitates timer)
OH, I GET IT.
PIZZA--ITALIAN POLICE HORN.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
I MEAN, THAT LOOKS JUST
ABOUT PERFECTLY CRISPY.
AGAIN, THE MOUTH'S
STARTIN' TO WATER.
SOME, UM, SUPER-FRESH BASIL
COMES OFF THE FARM AS WELL.
YOU WANT A KNIFE?
A FORK?
NOPE, JUST A TREADMILL.
MMM.
I LIKE THE CRUST
'CAUSE IT'S GOT A LITTLE--
LITTLE CHAR.
HUGE CHEESE FLAVOR.
NICE CREAMINESS.
THERE'S THAT FRESH MOZZARELLA.
ONION--
YOU GET THE RED ONION,
NICE LITTLE SWEET-
SOUR BITE OF THAT.
THE SAUCE IS RE--
LEGITIMATE.
CHICKEN'S GOT A ROAST TO IT.
AND THE BASIL IS JUST
SO FORWARD, RIGHT THERE.
THIS IS A PIZZA
CHAIN KILLER.
MMM. GOTTA GET THIS.
THE FRESH INGREDIENTS--
IT'S MUCH MORE FLAVORFUL.
YOU CAN WALK ALONG
WHERE IT'S GROWING,
AND CAN SEE,
"OKAY, WHAT'S COMING UP HERE
THAT'S GONNA BE IN SEASON?"
GREAT QUALITY
INGREDIENTS,
AND THE BEST-QUALITY INGREDIENTS
ARE THE ONES THAT ARE FRESH.
THIS IS VERY UNIQUE.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GREAT.
MY WIFE HAD HER FIRST
CHEESEBURGER HERE AND SAID,
"WE'VE GOTTA MOVE HERE.
I DON'T CARE WHAT IT COSTS.
WE'VE GOTTA MOVE HERE."
I WAS PREGNANT
AND REALLY INTO FOOD.
I MUST BE PREGNANT.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(barks like seal)
OH-HO-HO!
A WINNER!
(Guy) WHO IS THIS
RIGHT HERE?
THAT PICTURE IS YOU.
MY NEW LOOK.