HI, EVERYBODY.
I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
IT'S A FAMILY PLACE,
AND WE TAKE PRIDE IN IT.
THIS TRIP...
ONE MEDIUM-RARE
BEEF ON A ROLL.
A MOFONGO DE CARMEN.
IT'S ALL IN THE FAMILY.
WHO TAUGHT HIM
HOW TO COOK?
ME.
IN BALTIMORE...
LET ME HAVE
RARE PIT BEEF.
WE'RE GOING FOR
THE LOCAL FAVORITE--PIT BEEF.
IS THIS THE BEST PIT BEEF
IN BALTIMORE?
YES, IT IS.
WITH A MEMBER OF OUR
FOOD NETWORK FAMILY...
HOW YOU DOING?
NICE TO SEE YOU.
"ACE OF CAKES"
DUFF GOLDMAN.
OH, CHECK THAT OUT.
AND A LOCAL LEGEND THIS COUPLE
GOT AS A WEDDING PRESENT.
THEY CAME FROM DELAWARE
TO GET SOME PIT BEEF.
IN MIAMI...
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME HOT SAUCE?
WHERE ONE FAMILY'S
MAKING A SMASH HIT...
I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD BE
JOGGING IN PLACE OR SOMETHING.
WITH THEIR
PUERTO RICAN FAVORITES...
YEAH, THIS IS
THE REAL DEAL.
LIKE SOMETHING CALLED MOFONGO.
WOW. DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND MOFONGO.
AND NORTH
OF SALT LAKE CITY...
TWO DOUBLES
AND A SINGLE!
BIG BURGERS
AT A CLASSIC DRIVE-IN.
GOSH, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THAT'S BEEN IN THIS FAMILY
FOR 52 YEARS.
EVERYBODY'S WORKED HERE?
YOU'VE GOT
TO CHIP IN.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
AT TRIPLE D, WHEN WE HIT AN
HISTORIC PLACE LIKE BALTIMORE,
WELL, WE GOTTA USE THE INSIDE
TRACK OF A BUDDY WHO LIVES HERE.
SO REGARDLESS OF THE WEATHER
OR HOW BUSY THIS DUDE IS,
WE'RE AT CHARM CITY CAKES
TO TALK TO THE CAKE BAD BOY
DUFF GOLDMAN
AND FIND OUT ONE
OF HIS FAVORITE JOINTS.
CALL THE COPS.
THIS WHERE
THE MAGIC HAPPENS?
HOW YOU DOING?
NICE TO SEE YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
SO YOU OPEN
UP THE BAKERY.
YOU'VE BEEN DOING THIS THING
HERE, BUT YOUR REALLY COME
FROM A CULINARY BACKGROUND,
NOT JUST A BACKGROUND
OF MAKING INCREDIBLE CAKES.
I'VE BEEN A COOK
FOR ALMOST 20 YEARS.
I COME TO BALTIMORE. I WANT TO
TRY SOME ICONIC BALTIMORE FOOD.
LOCALS KNOW YOU
GOTTA GET PIT BEEF.
SO WHERE'S THE BEST
PLACE TO GET IT?
I THINK PROBABLY CHAPS.
CHAPS. LET'S GET
SOME PIT BEEF.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S
DO IT. OH, SWEET.
ISN'T THAT NICE?
COME ON,
LET ME DRIVE.
SERIOUSLY.
SERIOUSLY. CAN I?
NO.
AW, COME ON.
I DIDN'T GET
TO MAKE ANY CAKE.
THIS THING IS AWESOME.
THAT WAY.
THIS IS
THE FAMOUS CHAPS?
THIS IS CHAPS.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU COME TO BALTIMORE,
THIS IS WHAT YOU BETTER SEE.
AND IF YOU DON'T,
IT'S NOT GOOD BEEF.
GOOD CHARCOAL PIT BEEF--YOU'RE
NOT GONNA GET IT NOWHERE ELSE.
ONE MEDIUM-RARE BEEF
ON A ROLL.
IT IS SO TENDER.
JUST FALLS RIGHT APART.
MMM.
LET ME HAVE
RARE PIT BEEF.
DONE THE WAY YOU WANT...
MEDIUM WELL
AND A MEDIUM RARE.
THEN SLICED THIN...
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
AND PILED HIGH.
BEST PIT BEEF
EVER, MAN.
WHEN ANYBODY SAYS CHAPS, THEY
KNOW WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
IT STARTED 21 YEARS AGO
WHEN BOB AND DONNA CREAGER
GOT MARRIED.
AS A WEDDING GIFT, MY FATHER
GAVE ME THIS LITTLE SHACK.
FOR LAWN TOOLS
OR WHAT WAS THE REASON?
WELL, NO, HE SAID SINCE
MY HUSBAND LOVED TO COOK,
WE SHOULD PUT A PIT BEEF STAND
OUTSIDE OF HIS NIGHTCLUB.
FRY AND A RARE.
WE STARTED JUST A GRILL
AND AN EXHAUST SYSTEM
AND A REGISTER.
AND LEARNED REAL QUICK.
TWO BEEF ON A ROLL.
THANK YOU.
BRINGING IN SO MANY FANS, THEY
HAD TO ADD ON A DINING ROOM.
SOMEBODY GET
THE COUNTER, PLEASE.
BUT THE BEEF
IS STILL THE SAME.
IS THIS THE BEST
PIT BEEF OF ALL TIME?
YES, IT IS.
NOW THIS IS...
IT'S A BOTTOM ROUND.
YOU'LL PUT ABOUT SIX
OF THESE ON TO START THE DAY.
YOU CAN SMELL IT FROM AS EARLY
AS PROBABLY 6:00 IN THE MORNING.
ONCE I SMELLED THAT SMOKE,
I SAID I GOT TO GET OVER HERE.
WE'RE JUST STRAIGHT
ON THE GRILL JUST LIKE IT IS,
400 OR 500 DEGREES
USUALLY.
BAKER BOY,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S ABOUT RIGHT.
I'LL MELT THE GOLD.
WHERE'D YOUR BLING GO?
CAN YOU GET PART MEDIUM RARE
AND PART WELL DONE?
HERE YOU CAN GET
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
NEED A MEDIUM
AND A MEDIUM RARE.
THEY'RE BOTH RARE?
YES, SIR.
GOOD.
YOU GOT THREE
MEDIUM WELLS.
I LIKE RARE
MORE THAN ANYTHING.
FOR ORDER RARE, BRING IT
OVER TO THE EDGE, CUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW IN ABOUT 15 MINUTES, YOU'RE
READY TO START WORKING THAT.
WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO MAKE FIRST?
MAKE A BEEF SANDWICH.
YOU CAN DO IT. COME ON, NOW.
KEEP PUSHING IT.
IT GOT TO THE POINT WHERE
IT'S REALLY ON THE RARE SIDE.
RIGHT.
I MEAN, WE'RE ALMOST
TARTARE RIGHT THERE.
SO THAT GOES
BACK ON THE GRILL,
AND THEN WE'LL BRING
ANOTHER PIECE OUT.
THIS IS LIKE TAG-TEAM
MEAT SLICING.
EXACTLY.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT
OVER THERE.
CHECK THAT OUT. OH. NOW WHAT DO
YOU LIKE TO PUT ON THESE?
ONIONS, MAYBE
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
A LITTLE HORSERADISH
ON THERE.
MMM.
NOW HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU GUYS SELL IN A DAY?
A COUPLE HUNDRED.
YOU KNOW, I LIKE
THE LITTLE CHAR TO IT,
BUT I GOTTA SAY THE MEDLEY
OF THE WHITE ONION,
THE REALLY NICE
BRIGHT HORSERADISH,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
AND PEPPER, A GREAT ROLL--
NOT TOO MUCH BREAD.
I HATE WHEN
YOU GET TOO MUCH BREAD
AND IT STARTS
TO BECOME...
NO, IT'S ALL
ABOUT THE MEAT.
RIGHT.
(moans)
THAT'LL JUST BLING
YOU RIGHT OUT, WON'T IT? WOW!
THAT WAS
ALL HORSERADISH.
IT'S GOOD FOR YOU.
WHOA.
THERE IT IS.
MY TOES ARE TINGLING.
USUALLY I
GET, LIKE--WOW!
WELCOME TO BALTIMORE.
IT'S SPICY. IT'S MOIST.
THE MEAT IS SO TENDER.
I GIVE IT
WAY PAST A TEN.
AND THERE'S
WAY MORE THAN BEEF.
THREE TURKEYS.
THEY'RE PUTTING
EVERYTHING ON THE PIT.
IF YOU WANT A VARIETY,
THEY'VE GOT HAM, TURKEY.
I LIKE IT.
AND THEN, OF COURSE, SAUSAGE,
TOO. THAT'S ANOTHER GOOD CHOICE.
OH, YEAH. WHAT DO
YOU GOT THERE, MEAT WIZARD?
CORNED BEEF.
YEP, THEY'RE EVEN
PIT-GRILLING THE CORNED BEEF
FOR KILLER REUBENS
AND COMBOS ANY WAY YOU WANT.
(speaking indistinctly)
I THINK WE SHOULD
HAVE IT EVERY SINGLE WAY
YOU CAN POSSIBLY MAKE IT.
MY FAVORITE
IS A BULLDOG.
A COUPLE OF SLICES OF CHEESE,
THEN WE PUT THE SAUSAGE ON,
PUT THE BEEF ON.
GET UP UNDERNEATH
IT LIKE THIS.
BRING YOUR SHOULDERS--
PROJECT YOURSELF
WHEN YOU'RE
AT THE COUNTER.
YOU'RE COMING TO MY TOWN
AND TEACH ME HOW TO BULLDOG?
I DIDN'T THINK THE PIT BEEF
COULD GET ANY BETTER.
THAT LITTLE
SAUSAGE KICKER... MMM.
THIS ONE'S GOT PIT BEEF,
HAM AND CORNED BEEF.
IS THERE ANYTHING WRONG
WITH THIS PICTURE?
ACTUALLY, NO, THERE'S NOT.
WHEN THE BREAD
WON'T EVEN WRAP AROUND.
(Guy) THAT IS SO MUCH FLAVOR--
SWEETNESS OF THE HAM,
THAT BRINY, PICKLE-Y SPICE
ON THE CORNED BEEF,
AND THERE'S THE NICE SMOKY
FLAVOR FROM THE PIT BEEF,
A ROLL THAT CAN WITHSTAND
THE PRESSURE.
THIS IS LIKE SANDWICH
ENGINEERING RIGHT HERE.
GOOD MOUTH FEEL.
IT IS.
YOU SO WANT A BITE
OF THIS, DON'T YOU?
MMM. THIS
IS GREAT, MAN.
WELL, I LIKE EVERYTHING
WE GOT IN HERE.
I NEED A RIB AND CHICKEN
BARBECUE FOR A CALL-IN.
THEY GOT THE BEST SMOKY FLAVOR
IN THE WHOLE TOWN.
SAME AS ALWAYS
FOR TWO DECADES.
IT'S LIKE ONE OF OUR FAMILY
MEMBER'S HOUSES
AND THEY GOT
THE GRILL OUT...
HAVE A NICE DAY,
SIR. THANK YOU.
EXCEPT THEY'RE ALWAYS OPEN
AND DON'T MIND YOU STOPPING BY.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
THANK YOU.
AND HE CAME FROM DELAWARE
TO GET SOME PIT BEEF.
YEAH, I WANT THE BEEF
AND TURKEY.
YOU MAKE THESE GREAT COMBOS. NOW
CAN I CUSTOM-BUILD MY OWN COMBO?
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
FOR MY BOY
DUFF? YEAH?
START WITH THE BEEF.
SOME JALAPEÑOS DOWN,
HORSERADISH.
OKAY, NOW PUT
THE HAM UP THERE.
CUT THE BURGER
IN HALF.
NACHO CHEESE SAUCE.
SAUSAGE.
PICKLES, A LITTLE
CHOPPED BEEF, TURKEY.
WHERE ARE YOU DUFFINATOR?
MY BROTHER--THAT. JUST
LOOK AT THE CASCADING JOY.
THERE YOU GO.
THERE'S A CHAMPION.
LET'S CUT
THIS IN HALF.
NO, NO, NO!
DON'T CUT IT!
NO?
DON'T. IF YOU CUT IT,
IT'S GONNA EXPLODE.
LOOK AT THE BITE
OUT OF THAT.
MAKE SURE YOU
DON'T LOSE ANYTHING.
GET OVER HERE.
OH! HE GOES FOR
A DOUBLE BITE. WHAT CHEESE?
YOU GOT SOME...
IS THERE ANYTHING RIGHT HERE?
NO, YOU LOOK FUNNY.
UP NEXT...
IF YOU WENT TO PUERTO RICE,
THAT'S HOW IT WOULD TASTE?
THAT'S HOW
IT WOULD
WE'RE HEADING TO MIAMI
FOR A FAMILY RECIPE...
JUST AS GOOD
AS GRANDMA'S.
YOU JUST CAN'T BEAT.
YOU WANT TO TRY?
WELL, JUST GET
ANGRY WITH IT.
WHEN I ROLL INTO AN AREA THAT
I'M NOT REALLY FAMILIAR WITH,
I LOVE TO CHECK OUT
THE PLACES AND THE FOOD
THAT ONLY THE LOCALS KNOW ABOUT.
SO HERE I AM IN MIAMI,
AND I'M TOLD I GOTTA GO SEE
A GUY NAMED BENNY AND HIS FAMILY
AND TRY THE MOFONGO.
MOFONGO? OH, THIS IS
GONNA BE INTERESTING.
GOT AN ORDER
OF MOFONGO.
A MOFONGO DE CARMEN.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
THIS IS THE BEST DISH,
JUST AS GOOD AS GRANDMA'S.
TRADITIONAL,
PUERTO RICO STYLE.
AUTHENTIC.
YEP.
IT'S PLANTAINS
SMASHED UP WITH GARLIC
WITH PORK, CHICKEN,
BEEF OR SEAFOOD.
AND ALSO CHICHARRóN,
WHICH IS PORK RINDS.
THESE ARE
THE PORK FAT?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
OH!
TASTES JUST LIKE
BACK HOME IN PUERTO RICO.
'CAUSE THAT'S HOW BENNY OJEDA'S
MOM TAUGHT HIM TO MAKE IT,
WHEN HE AND HIS WIFE WANDA
WERE GROWING UP
IN THE SAME COASTAL TOWN.
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME HOT SAUCE?
WHEN THEY CAME TO MIAMI
ABOUT 20 YEARS AGO
AND COULDN'T FIND A PUERTO
RICAN RESTAURANT THEY LIKED...
IT'S ALMOST DONE.
THEY OPENED THEIR OWN.
IT'S ALL FAMILY.
MY MOTHER-IN-LAW COMES AND SHE
COOKS A LOT OF THE THINGS.
AND THE KIDS
COME AND WORK HERE?
THEY RUN EVERYTHING NOW.
BUT ASK THEM
WHO'S IN CHARGE.
(both) MY MOM.
MOM.
YEAH, DEFINITELY.
YOU NEED TO GO
TO A TABLE.
YOU NEED TO GO TO THE KITCHEN
AND YOU BACK TO THE KITCHEN.
WHO TAUGHT HIM
HOW TO COOK?
ME.
AND THE REASON THAT
I KNOW IT'S AUTHENTIC--
IT'S 'CAUSE SHE'S HERE.
(speaking Spanish) CALIENTE!
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
MOFONGO.
THE MOFONGO
WITH FRIED CHICKEN.
YOU HAVE
MOFONGO PORK, SHRIMP.
THE SIDE ORDERS ARE
WHAT WE PUT IN THE TOP,
BUT THE MOFONGO'S
ALWAYS THE SAME BASICS.
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
CUT UP THE PLANTAIN
AND WE PUT IT IN THE FRYER.
WE DO THE COMBINATION
OF SALT, GARLIC.
MIX OUT HERE FIRST,
WE GRIND IT UP,
AND THEN WE PUT
THE PLANTAIN INSIDE.
WE GONNA DO--
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT IS THIS BOWL?
WHERE DO YOU BUY THIS?
THIS ONE IS CUSTOM-MADE
IN PUERTO RICO.
AND WITH SOMETHING
LIKE THIS THEY MASH IT UP.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
HE'S GOT A BIG GIANT OAK LOG
WITH A BASEBALL BAT.
SO WE PUT
THIS ONE IN...
GARLIC, SALT, CHICHARRóNES.
AND THEN WE HIT IT.
WE'RE GONNA BE JUMPING
A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS MORTAR
AND PESTLE GONE WILD.
HOW DO YOU
GET IT OUT OF THERE?
I HAVE A BIG
LONG SPOON TO GET IT OUT,
AND THEN WE
PUT IT HERE AGAIN.
THE PLANTAIN IS READY
AND THEN OUR SEASONING.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE OLIVE OIL,
AND THEN YOU HAVE TO HIT
IT IN A SPECIFIC WAY
SO THE PLANTAINS GO...
SO YOU MOVE IT
UP AND DOWN.
EXACTLY. YOU WANT
TO TRY?
WELL, JUST GET ANGRY WITH IT.
YEAH, I'LL GET IN ON THIS.
YOU GOT THE IDEA.
LET ME
GIVE YOU A HAND.
I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD BE JOGGING
IN PLACE OR SOMETHING.
AND EVERY TIME THAT SOMEONE
ORDERS THIS, YOU DO THIS?
EXACTLY. THIS IS
WHEN IT'S DONE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
THE MEAT FOR THE MOFONGO.
WE'RE JUST GONNA LEAVE
THIS BAT-BEATEN
FRIED PLANTAIN, CHICHARRóN
GARLIC MESS IN HERE?
YES.
GOOD.
SO THIS IS THE PORK.
HOW LONG WILL THIS FRY?
ONLY FIVE MINUTE OR LESS,
BECAUSE IT'S ALREADY COOKED.
THEN WE PUT
THE MOFONGO IN HERE,
AND THEN WE PUT
THE MEAT AT THE TOP.
WE EAT IT WITH
SOME CHICKEN CONSOMMé.
SO THE MEAT IS
MORE SOFT AND TENDER.
WOW. THIS IS AWESOME.
BUT YOU GET
THE LITTLE BITE.
OH, THE CRUNCHY.
OH! THIS IS BANANAS--
I MEAN, PLANTAINS.
PLANTAINS IS GOOD.
IT'S THE BEST
ONE AROUND.
WHAT I LOVE THE MOST IS
THE SEASONING AND THE GARLIC.
AND IT'S NOT JUST PORK.
BENNY DOES MOFONGO
TEN DIFFERENT WAYS.
THIS IS RED SNAPPER.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME BUTTER,
GARLIC, CILANTRO AND CULANTRO.
YOUR WINE--YOU'RE GONNA NEED
A LITTLE EXTRA FLAVOR.
OH, FANTASTIC.
THAT IS FRESH, MAN.
IT'S FUN.
MM-HMM.
IT'S MO-FUN-GO.
MOFONGO TIME.
YOU WANT TO TRY
THE SHRIMP?
DO I HAVE TO?
YOU'RE GONNA
LOVE THIS ONE.
SHRIMP MOFONGO--
REALLY TENDER,
GENTLE SHRIMP.
DUDE, I AM
SO IMPRESSED.
THAT MIGHT BE SERIOUSLY
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
I'VE EVER TRIED
ON TRIPLE D.
HE'S A WIZARD!
JUST AMAZING.
YOU CAN SMELL THE GARLIC
WHEN YOU GET THE DISH.
A LITTLE SALTY, TOO,
AND THEN YOU HAVE
THE SHRIMP TO OFFSET IT
WITH THAT SEAFOOD FLAVOR,
SO IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE SAME
AS IN PUERTO RICO.
WHATEVER BENNY'S SERVING,
LIKE SHREDDED, DEEP-FRIED
PLANTAINS CALLED SPIDERS
OR TOSTONES.
YOU TAKE THESE
AND COOK 'EM A LITTLE BIT
AND THEN PRESS 'EM AND THEN COOK
'EM AGAIN--THOSE ARE TOSTONES?
EXACTLY.
IF YOU WENT TO PUERTO RICO,
THAT'S HOW IT WOULD TASTE?
THAT'S HOW
IT WOULD TASTE.
OR SOUND.
(makes high-pitched sound)
SO THIS IS CONCH. THIS IS
WHAT'S INSIDE THE SHELL.
EXACTLY.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
TASTES LIKE LOBSTER SALAD.
THIS IS DYNAMITE, MAN.
AND A TASTE OF HOME
IN A FAMILY PLACE.
THEN WE HAVE
THE CONCH SALAD.
I'M GREETED IN SPANISH. THAT
GIVES IT A WHOLE FEEL FOR ME.
THEY SEE THAT FAMILY AMBIENCE.
THE MEALS FEEL LIKE
THEY'VE BEEN HOME-COOKED.
ALL THE WAY DOWN
TO HOLIDAY FAVORITES.
THIS DISH HERE IS THE TYPICAL
CHRISTMASTIME DISH.
RICE AND PIGEON PEAS,
BOILED GREEN BANANA DOUGH
AND ROAST PORK.
LET'S MAKE
THE SEASONING FOR IT.
THE SEASONING FIRST? OKAY.
SALT, OREGANO, GARLIC.
WE'VE GOT THE PEPPER.
SO THESE
ARE ANNATTO SEEDS?
MM-HMM.
PUT 'EM IN BOILING OIL.
THEY MAKE THE OIL RED,
AND THEN YOU STRAIN THEM OUT.
AND THEN OLIVE OIL.
THIS IS SAZóN.
SAZóN. THAT'S A SEASONING.
IT'S A COMBINATION
OF SEASONINGS TOGETHER.
AND YOU BUY THAT.
YEAH.
THE LAST IS VINEGAR
AND THEN POP IT IN THE OVEN.
FOR HOW LONG
AND WHAT TEMPERATURE?
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
FOR 5 HOURS, 350.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD FLAVOR.
THAT RICE IS PHENOMENAL.
THESE PEAS ARE
CALLED PIGEON PEAS?
YEAH, OR GANDULES.
IT'S LIKE A BIG GIANT
LENTIL. THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
(speaking indistinctly)
THAT'S RIGHT HERE.
HOMEGROWN FOOD--VERY, VERY GOOD.
IT'S VERY TASTY.
FROM CHRISTMAS DINNER
TO MOFONGO...
YEAH, THIS IS
THE REAL DEAL.
HE LIKES TO MAKE SURE
THE FOOD THAT HE GIVES TO PEOPLE
IS LIKE SOMETHING
HE GOT FROM HIS GRANDMOTHER.
AND MOTHER.
DOES IT MAKE
YOU FEEL PROUD?
SI, SI.
IT'S A FAMILY BUSINESS.
ARE THEY
GONNA TAKE OVER?
JOSHUA WILL BE BEN,
AND JEFFRY WILL BE ME.
AND THAT'S WHAT I WANT
FOR MY SON, ALSO.
IF WE CAN KEEP THIS GOING,
I WOULD LOVE FOR MY SON
TO WORK
WITH ME HERE.
FEELS LIKE
A GOOD FAMILY PLACE.
OH, YEAH, IT IS.
YOU, YOUR WIFE
AND THE BOYS.
YES.
AND THE MOFONGO.
I JUST CHANGED THE NAMES--
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND MOFONGO.
THAT'S GOOD.
WOW.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE GOING TO UTAH...
YOU CAN'T GET A BURGER THAT
TASTES LIKE THIS ANYWHERE ELSE.
WHERE ONE FAMILY'S
BEEN BUILDING THE BURGERS
FOR HALF A CENTURY.
YOU WANT TO WRAP THIS?
I DON'T EVEN THINK
I COULD SING ABOUT IT.
SO I'M KICKIN' IT
HERE IN ROY, UTAH.
NOW SALT LAKE CITY'S
LIKE 30 MILES THAT WAY.
15 MILES THAT WAY
IS SOME KILLER SKIING,
BUT FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE
THIS IS THE DESTINATION--
A LITTLE BURGER JOINT
THAT'S BEEN DOING IT RIGHT
FOR OVER 52 YEARS.
YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT
THE BURGER BAR.
TWO SINGLES AND A DOUBLE.
SMALL FRY, PLEASE.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU CAN'T GET A BURGER THAT
TASTES LIKE THIS ANYWHERE ELSE.
IT'S BIG, AND IT'S
GOT A LOT OF MEAT.
AND I NEED THAT
C-BURGER PRETTY QUICK.
THE SINGLE'S A QUARTER-POUND,
AND THEY'LL STACK 'EM...
THREE DOUBLE CHEESEBURGERS.
FROM DOUBLE TO QUAD
AND EVEN BIGGER.
LOOK AT THAT, HUH?
THAT'S A GOOD BURGER.
AND ALL THE OTHER
DRIVE-IN CLASSICS.
CAN YOU GET
ME A FOOT-LONG?
AND THE ONION RINGS
ARE MY FAVORITE.
DEFINITELY THE FRIES.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
AND ALL SERVED UP
WITH A UTAH FAVORITE.
(woman) WOULD YOU LIKE
EXTRA FRY SAUCE?
IT'S AMAZING, BUT FRY SAUCE
GOES WITH ANYTHING.
WE MAKE IT WITH SALAD
DRESSING AND KETCHUP.
WHERE WE COME FROM,
WE CALL THIS THOUSAND ISLAND.
BUT AROUND HERE
IT'S FRY SAUCE...
GOOD OL' UTAH
WITH OUR FRY SAUCE.
A LOCAL FAVORITE,
LIKE THE BURGER BAR ITSELF.
HEY, HOW LONG
YOU BEEN COMING HERE?
YEARS.
SINCE I WAS LITTLE.
OH, IT'S BEEN HERE A LONG TIME.
I THINK IT'S TRADITION.
I BUILT IT MYSELF.
AND I WAS WORKING
WITH A BABY ON MY BACK.
BEN AND RITA FOWLER OPENED
THE JOINT IN '56.
YOU WANT SAUCE
WITH YOUR FRY?
THE NEXT TWO GENERATIONS
FOLLOWED HIM INTO THE BUSINESS.
THANK YOU.
EVERYBODY'S WORKED HERE?
EVERYBODY. WE HAD TO.
IT WAS THE FAMILY FARM.
GOTTA CHIP IN.
AND THERE YOU GO.
HI, MAY I HELP YOU?
IT'S A FAMILY PLACE,
AND WE TAKE PRIDE IN IT.
OF THE SIBLINGS THAT WORK HERE,
YOU'RE KIND OF...
I'M A TOP DOG.
YOU'RE TOP DOG.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND JESSICA'S TOP JOB...
LA!
IS KEEPING EVERYTHING THE WAY
EVERYONE EXPECTS IT TO BE.
EVERYTHING IS SO FRESH.
IT'S BETTER THAN
ANY FAST-FOOD JOINT.
ARE THEY SHAKE SHAKES, OR ARE
THEY KIND OF PUNY SHAKES?
THEY'RE BIG.
HUGE SHAKES, ABOUT
THAT MUCH OVER THE RIM.
(Guy) NO KIDDING?
EVERYONE LIKES IT.
ESPECIALLY
THEIR SIGNATURE BURGER...
I WANT A CHEESE BEN.
THE QUARTER-POUNDER
CALLED "THE BIG BEN."
IT'S JUST
A GREAT HAMBURGER.
THE BEN IS OUR
SPECIALTY HAMBURGER.
IT'S NAMED
AFTER MY GRANDFATHER.
WHAT IS THAT?
THIS IS OUR ROUND
SLICED BACON, YEAH.
ROUND SLICE BACON? NOW
WHERE'S THE MEAT COME FROM?
THEY GRIND
THE MEAT DAILY.
SO IT'S NEVER FROZEN?
NO, AND WE LIKE TO PUT
OUR CHEESE ON SO IT'S MELTING,
AND WE TOAST OUR BUN.
COME OVER HERE.
YOU WANT TO ADD THE FRY SAUCE?
THINK YOU CAN
GIVE IT A SWIRL?
OH, DO IT THE WAY
YOU NORMALLY DO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
(whistles)
HAVE OUR PICKLE,
HAVE SOME TOMATO ON THERE.
THAT'S A BIG BURGER.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND THEN
IN THE SUMMER MONTHS,
THOSE TOMATOES
COME OUT OF OUR GARDEN.
THE BURGER'S REALLY JUICY.
THE BACON IS MONEY.
THE CHEESE MELTS NICE,
AND THEN THE FRY SAUCE...
OR THE THING THAT TIES IT ALL
TOGETHER IS THAT BUN.
MY FAVORITE PART
IS THE HOMEMADE BEN BUN.
GOSH, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
WE'LL GET A SINGLE.
WE DO DOUBLE.
WE CAN GO UP TO TRIPLES
AND QUADS, TOO.
THE CHEESE BEN
AND THE QUAD BURGERS
ARE WHAT WE'VE BEEN EATING.
THAT'S A FULL POUND OF BEEF,
BUT IT'S NOTHING
TO THIS CAT TYLER.
YOU'VE GOT THE RECORD OF EATING
THE BIGGEST BURGER HERE?
YES, I DO.
HOW MANY?
12 PATTIES.
12 PATTIES? HOW LONG
DID IT TAKE YOU?
HOUR AND FIVE MINUTES.
BUT TODAY HE'S CUTTING BACK,
JUST GOING FOR EIGHT.
YOU WANT TO WRAP THIS?
I DON'T EVEN THINK
I COULD SING ABOUT IT.
OH, WE GOT SOME CHEESE
ON THERE, TOO.
WELL, CHEESE
AND SOME OF THE SAUCE.
WHERE'S YOUR CHEERING CREW?
OH, MY WIFE'S
RIGHT OVER THERE.
ARE YOU CONDONING
THIS BEHAVIOR?
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU THINK YOUR DADDY
CAN EAT ALL THAT?
YES.
HOW LONG?
40 MINUTES.
GO.
OKAY. THAT'S
A GOOD BURGER.
WE'LL CHECK BACK A LITTLE LATER
AND SEE HOW HE'S DOING
WITH THE BIG B.
HE'S IN THE ZONE?
HE'S IN THE ZONE.
BUT IT'S NOT
JUST BEEF HERE.
WE NEED TWO
BUFFALO BURGERS.
TWO BUFFALO!
OUR EXOTIC MEATS
ARE BUFFALO AND OUR ELK.
LIKE REAL BUFFALO?
YEAH. I USUALLY PUT A LID
ON IT JUST TO, YOU KNOW,
KEEP THE MOISTURE IN IT
SO IT DOESN'T DRY OUT.
ALL RIGHT. GO WITH
THE FRY SAUCE AGAIN.
AT LEAST YOU DON'T
HOLD BACK ON THAT.
I'LL TAKE A BITE.
I THINK I LIKE THE BUFFALO
BETTER THAN THE BEEF.
DO YOU?
YEP. IT'S GOT
A MEATIER FLAVOR.
IT'S GOT GREAT TEXTURE.
THAT'S GOOD.
GOOD.
IT REALLY IS GOOD.
I'D SAY IT'S A LOT BETTER
THAN JUST A NORMAL HAMBURGER--
A LITTLE BIT LEANER.
WE HAVE FANS OF THE BUFFALO,
AND WE HAVE FANS OF THE ELK.
I AM HAVING
THE ELK BURGER TODAY.
LET'S TRY THE ELK.
OKAY.
AND WHERE'S
THE ELK COME FROM?
UTAH ELK, GOURMET ELK.
YOU EAT A LOT
OF THE ELK BURGERS?
UH-HUH.
I THINK THIS I WANT TO DO JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF SAUCE THOUGH.
LIGHT?
I DON'T WANT--
OH, THERE'S SUCH A THING.
MAN, THAT'S GOOD.
YOU LIKE IT?
IT'S LESS THAN 2 GRAMS
OF FAT, SO...
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
NOT GAMY.
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR,
INCREDIBLE TEXTURE--
EXCELLENT.
IT'S JUST A NICE
BREAK FROM BEEF.
AND SPEAKING OF BEEF...
I FEEL PRETTY GOOD.
REMEMBER TYLER, WHO'S SLAMMING
AN 8-PATTY BURGER?
I THINK I COULD
HAVE GONE FOR THE 12.
OH, WHY DON'T YOU KEEP AT IT.
WE'RE GONNA GO TO COMMERCIAL.
WHEN YOU COME BACK,
YOU'LL GET TO SEE
WHAT KIND OF DISASTER
HE'S MADE OUT OF THIS THING.
WE'RE AT THE BURGER BAR
IN ROY, UTAH.
YOU HAVE
THE TWO C-BENS, RIGHT?
FOUR BEN OLD-FASHIONED!
THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU MUCH.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
JUST A GOOD DRIVE-IN.
GET A NICE BIG BURGER.
TWO SINGLES
AND A DOUBLE.
THEY'VE BEEN CRANKING OUT
THE BURGERS FOR DECADES...
MAN, THAT'S GOOD.
AS BIG AS YOU WANT.
NO PROBLEM?
THAT'S A GOOD BURGER.
AND TYLER HERE
HAS BEEN DOING REAL DAMAGE
TO HIS 8-PATTY BURGER.
HOW MUCH TIME?
8 MINUTES
AND 37 SECONDS.
BUT HE'S NOT DONE YET, SO
WHILE TYLER'S TRYING TO FINISH,
WE'LL CHECK OUT WHAT
HE'S HAVING ON THE SIDE.
CAN I GET
A BEN FRY, PLEASE?
DEFINITELY THE FRIES.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN EVEN
GET 'EM TRIPLE FRIED.
FRY 'EM ONCE
IN THE MORNING...
UH-HUH, WE BLANCH THEM
JUST FOR A MINUTE--
JUST DO LIKE
PART OF THE COOKING
AND SO IT'LL COOK UP
FASTER AND MORE CRISP.
NOW HOW LONG
WILL THEY GO DOWN NOW?
THESE WILL GO DOWN
FOR TWO MINUTES.
SO THEY'LL GO FOR TWO MINUTES.
THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
THEN YOU PULL 'EM OUT?
THEN WE PULL EM UP,
AND WE LET THEM ACTUALLY--
REST AGAIN.
RIGHT,
AND THEN DROP 'EM BACK DOWN
WHEN THEY'RE READY TO GO OUT,
AND THEY STAY
CRISPY FOR A LOT LONGER.
THAT HAS GREAT CRUNCH.
EXCELLENT FRIES.
SAME WITH THE RINGS.
THE ONION RINGS ARE FANTASTIC.
YOU CAN TELL
THEY MAKE 'EM BY HAND.
ANY PARTICULAR TYPE OF ONION
THAT WE'RE WORKING WITH?
THE YELLOW ONION. THESE
HAVE BEEN SOAKED OVERNIGHT.
WE PUT 'EM JUST
IN OUR FLOUR HERE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE
SHAKE OFF THE EXCESS,
AND THEN WE
PUT BUTTERMILK.
WE JUST PUT THIS OVER HERE
IN OUR CRACKER, COAT IT.
THESE ARE
OUR ONION RINGS.
THIS IS THE BOAT
WE'LL USE TO PUT THEM IN.
HOW LONG?
ABOUT TWO
TO THREE MINUTES.
THAT ABOUT DONE?
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT--
CRISPY, CRUNCHY.
EXCELLENT.
THAT FRY SAUCE
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT--
MONEY? YOU LIKE IT?
YOU JUST
THROW OUT "MONEY"?
I DON'T KNOW.
IS THAT
HOW YOU ROLL?
THAT'S HOW I ROLL.
THEY'RE HAND-MADE, AND SO
YOU CAN TELL THEY'RE FRESH.
SO ARE THE HUGE SHAKES.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR BUTTERFINGER
AND YOUR RASPBERRY.
THAT'S WHY I COME HERE,
IS THE MILKSHAKES.
AND THEY'RE DOING
A LOCAL TAKE ON A LIME RICKY.
GRAPE, LIME AND SPRITE.
THAT'S REFRESHING.
BUT IT IS THE BURGER BAR.
WANT TO GO
FOR ANOTHER EIGHT?
AND HOW'S
MY BUDDY TYLER DOING?
ONE BITE
TO THE REST OF IT?
OKAY, YOU READY?
(laughter)
LOOK AT THAT.
AND AFTER PREDICTING
40 MINUTES...
WHAT WAS
THE TIME ON IT?
HE DID IT
IN LESS THAN 15.
TYLER, I GOTTA
TELL YOU, MAN--
FAIR AND SQUARE, BABY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DIDN'T DO BAD, DID HE?
MAKING ROY, UTAH, PROUD.
JUMP, I GOT YA.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY
MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE D.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
GIVE ME JAZZ HANDS.
HUH?
YOU KNOW WHAT
JAZZ HANDS ARE?
NO, I DON'T.
DID YOU EVER SEEN THIS?
GO LIKE THIS. JAZZ HANDS. OKAY.