HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(man) WHOO!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
FRESH BARBEQUE!
ALL KINDS OF BARBEQUE...
SAUSAGE AND BRISKET.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE
THING ON THE MENU?
RIBS.
WE LOVE
THE PULLED PORK.
(Guy) HOW'S THE REST OF IT?
OH, IT'S AMAZING.
IN TEXAS...
SOUTH TEXAS PERFECT BARBEQUE.
MMM. WILL YOU JUST
SQUIRT THIS IN MY MOUTH
AS I STICK
THIS WHOLE PIECE IN?
BARBEQUE WORTH
FLYING IN FOR.
IF THEY DIDN'T WANT
US TO LAND HERE,
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE PAINTED
BARBEQUE ON THE ROOF.
A NEW ORLEANS JOINT...
THEY COOK THE BEST BARBEQUE
I'VE EVER EATEN ANYWHERE.
DOING IT ALL...
YOU DESIGNED
YOUR OWN SMOKER?
THEIR OWN WAY.
JUST A PETE
DESIGN METHOD AND STYLE.
TRIAL AND ERROR,
MY FRIEND.
THAT'S KILLER.
(man) BRING IT ON.
BRING IT ON.
AND A SWEET TIME
IN MISSISSIPPI...
HOW MUCH SUGAR ARE YOU
GONNA PUT IN THIS THING?
AT A BARBEQUE DIVE...
YOU HAVE
A FULL RACK PLATE.
ABOUT AS TENDER
AS YOU GET.
WHERE THE OWNERS
GREW UP.
THIS WAS THE PATIO
TO THE DOUBLE-WIDE?
EXACTLY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO EVERYBODY IN TEXAS HAS THEIR
FAVORITE BARBEQUE JOINT, RIGHT?
YOU KNOW, SMALL LITTLE SHACK,
SERVES KILLER FOOD.
WELL, IN ADKINS, TEXAS, ABOUT
20 MILES EAST OF SAN ANTONIO,
IT'S NOT A LITTLE SHACK.
IT'S MORE LIKE
A CULINARY COMPOUND.
YOU GOTTA
CHECK OUT TEXAS PRIDE.
THAT RIGHT THERE
IS 100% FRESH.
THIS IS OUR FAVORITE
BARBEQUE PLACE.
YOU WANT
THAT MARBLE IN?
I CAN EAT THIS BARBEQUE
THREE TIMES A DAY.
SOUTH TEXAS BARBEQUE AIN'T FROM
CHICAGO. IT AIN'T YANKEE.
IT AIN'T SWEET. IT AIN'T SOUR.
IT'S SMOKED.
POUND AFTER POUND
OF RIBS, CHICKEN,
SAUSAGE AND SIGNATURE
TEXAS BRISKET.
LAST YEAR WE GOT VOTED
THE NUMBER ONE PLACE
IN SAN ANTONIO TO TAKE
OUT-OF-TOWN GUESTS.
WE USUALLY COME IN
WHENEVER FAMILY COMES IN.
WE LIKE TO BRING
THEM OUT HERE.
EVERY TIME THEY COME,
EVERYBODY WALKS AWAY HAPPY.
IT'S BEEN THAT WAY SINCE 1922,
WHEN STEVE TALANKO
OPENED A RESTAURANT
IN A SAN ANTONIO GAS STATION.
SAUSAGE AND BRISKET.
MORE THAN EIGHT DECADES LATER,
HIS GRANDSON TONY
IS KEEPING THE LEGACY ALIVE.
EVERY TIME WE PASS BY,
GOTTA STOP.
MOST PEOPLE HAVE TO DRIVE 20
MINUTES OR MORE TO GET TO US.
IT'S DEFINITELY WORTH
THE DRIVE TO COME OUT HERE.
THEY'RE EVEN DROPPING IN.
YOU FLY IN
FOR BARBEQUE?
ABSOLUTELY.
IF THEY DIDN'T
WANT US TO LAND HERE,
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE PAINTED
BARBEQUE ON THE ROOF.
DOES IT SAY
BARBEQUE ON THE ROOF?
HOW DO YOU
THINK WE FIND IT?
ONCE THEY STOP,
WE'VE GOT 'EM.
YOU KNOW, THEY TRY OUR
BARBEQUE AND THEY COME BACK.
BEYOND THE SHOW,
THE BARBEQUE IS TEXAS BASIC.
TEXAS IS A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF THE DRY RUB AND COOK IT
AND THEN ADD
SOME SAUCE LATER.
AWESOME.
IT'S SMOKED
WITH REAL MESQUITE WOOD,
AND IT TASTES
LIKE SMOKE.
OUR FAVORITE THING
IS THE RIBS.
I REALLY LIKE THE SAUSAGE.
I GO MORE FOR THE BRISKET.
I'M MORE OF A BRISKET PERSON.
WHAT IS THE NUMBER ONE-SELLING
ITEM IN THE RESTAURANT?
BRISKET.
QUARTER POUND OF BRISKET.
THIS IS IT--SEASON SALT, BLACK
PEPPER, GRANULATED GARLIC?
GRANULATED GARLIC.
NOW I LIKE MY BRISKET
WITH A TON OF PEPPER.
YEAH, THAT'S
WHAT WE LIKE.
AM I KIND OF PEPPERING THIS
ENOUGH, OR DO YOU WANT--
EVEN A LITTLE MORE.
THERE YOU GO.
THIS HERE IS
A BIG PIECE OF MEAT.
SO YOU NEED TO BE ABLE
TO INCORPORATE
TO HAVE THOSE FLAVORS, TO HAVE
ENOUGH FOR ALL THAT MEAT VOLUME.
SO THESE ARE
GONNA GO DOWN 12 HOURS.
CHECK 'EM.
OKAY.
IF THEY'RE NOT DONE,
WRAP 'EM UP,
LEAVE 'EM ON THE PIT
FOR ANOTHER COUPLE HOURS.
ALL RIGHT.
WOW.
FROM THIS MONSTER PIECE
THAT WE WERE TO THIS.
OH, LOOK AT THAT. YOU DIDN'T
EVEN NEED A KNIFE.
YOU COULD HAVE DONE THAT
JUST WITH LASER VISION.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
IF WE JUST PUSH ON THAT.
SEE ALL THAT JUICE JUST COMING
OUT OF THAT? (whistles)
WHACK ME OFF
A SLICE OF THAT. MMM.
NICE BARK.
WELL, THE 12 HOURS,
THAT'S WHAT THAT DOES TO IT.
JUST GIVE ME
THE CRUST.
TRY A LITTLE BIT
WITH THE BARBEQUE SAUCE.
NOW THIS IS THE HOT?
THIS IS
THE HOTTER ONE.
MMM. WILL YOU JUST
SQUIRT THIS IN MY MOUTH
AS I STICK
THIS WHOLE PIECE IN?
IT'S VERY SIMPLE,
STRAIGHTFORWARD,
AND YOU USE GOOD MEAT,
COOK IT THE RIGHT WAY,
DON'T OVERSEASON IT,
DON'T OVERSMOKE IT,
TOP IT OFF WITH
A DYNAMITE BARBEQUE SAUCE.
THIS HERE IS HOMEMADE
BARBEQUE SAUCE.
AT SOUTH TEXAS,
YOU GOTTA HAVE REAL SAUCE.
THE SAUCE IS EXCELLENT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND COMPLETELY UNIQUE.
IT STARTS WITH CARAMELIZED
ONIONS IN BACON FAT,
COOKS DOWN
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
IT'S REALLY
BROWNS THE SAUCE
AND GIVES IT
ITS KIND OF UNIQUE FLAVOR.
REGULAR AND SPICY.
SAUCE IS GOOD.
HAS A LITTLE KICK TO IT.
GOTTA HAVE BITE.
NOW BARBEQUE SAUCE--
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE?
I SEE YOU'VE GOT
THE HOT OUT THERE.
YEAH, I LIKE
THE SPICY.
SO THAT'S
THE WAY TO ROLL?
(man) THAT'S THE WAY
TO DO IT.
BUT AT SOME TABLES,
THAT'S UP FOR DEBATE.
I LIKE DRY BARBEQUE.
IF IT'S NOT MESSY,
IT'S NOT GOOD.
HE CAN GET HIS WET BARBEQUE,
AND I CAN GET MY DRY BARBEQUE.
THEY CALL IT WET.
I CALL IT GOOD.
THAT'S WET BARBEQUE.
BUT SAUCE ISN'T THE ONLY CHOICE
YOU GOTTA MAKE HERE.
HOW DO YOU
WANT THAT CUT?
YOU CAN GET IT
THICK, THIN.
FAT OR LEAN...
ABSOLUTELY NO FAT.
LEAN, TRIM,
SMOKED JUST RIGHT.
DINNERS OR SANDWICHES.
TEXAS IS BIG, YOU KNOW, SO
YOU GOTTA GET A BIG SANDWICH.
AND ALL
THE LOCAL FAVORITES.
SAUSAGE AND THE GERMAN
POTATO SALAD--IT'S GREAT.
DID YOU WANT ANY OF THE SIDE
ORDERS OR ANYTHING?
HOW MANY DIFFERENT
SIDES WE OFFER?
WE GOT PINTO BEANS,
GREEN BEANS, COLESLAW,
MACARONI SALAD AND FRIES.
THE FRENCH FRIES
ARE DELICIOUS.
THEY HAVE
THE SEASONING SALT ON IT.
DO YOU DO
A DOUBLE FRY ON THOSE?
WE BLANCHE 'EM, YEAH.
AND THEN YOU'LL
THROW 'EM DOWN AGAIN,
AND THEN THAT'LL PUT
THE CRISP ON 'EM.
EXACTLY.
THE ONLY WAY TO DO
FRESH-CUT FRIES.
YOU CAN'T EAT
BARBEQUE WITHOUT BEANS.
THE BACON--YOU'RE JUST
USING IT FOR THE FAT?
THAT'S IT.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE BACON FLAVOR.
BACON FLAVOR.
SOME GROUND ONIONS. WE'RE NOT
EVEN GONNA CALL THOSE CHOPPED.
THEY'RE JUST
GONNA DISINTEGRATE.
FLAVOR, THAT'S ALL.
SO THE BACON'S
NOT CRISPY,
BUT WE STARTED TO RENDER
DOWN THE FAT?
YES.
NOW WE WANT THAT FAT TO BE
ABLE TO COOK THESE ONIONS IN.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
JUST CARAMELIZE THEM
SO THE ONIONS
AND BACON ARE GOING.
THEY'VE COOKED DOWN
TO A POINT WHERE I CAN JUST
SPOON THAT
ON SOME TOAST.
GOT SALT, GARLIC POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER.
MY FAVORITE ONE--
COMINOS.
COMINOS. THAT'S WHAT I GREW UP
IS MEXICAN PRONUNCIATION.
THEY DIDN'T SAY CUMIN.
THEY SAID COMINOS.
IF THAT ISN'T A MASSIVE
FLAVOR MASS RIGHT THERE,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IS.
(whistles)
GONNA ADD
THE WATER NOW.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
COUPLE HOURS.
THESE ARE DONE?
YES.
(growls)
WAS THAT LIKE A SMALL GROWL
THAT JUST CAME OUT?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT WAS.
THAT WAS GOOD.
NOT TOO SALTY. I GRABBED
A LITTLE BIT OF THE PEPPER.
I COULD CHUG
THE BEAN JUICE.
YEAH.
I LIKE TO PUT OUR HOT
AND SPICY BARBEQUE SAUCE
RIGHT IN TOP OF THIS.
REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THE BEANS?
BEANS ARE AWESOME
AND IT DOES GET--YOU KNOW,
GOT A NICE FLAVOR TO IT
AND A LITTLE BIT OF PORK TO IT.
NOT OVERLY DONE, NOT TOO MUCH,
NOT TOO SUGARY, NOTHING.
BEANS ARE ALWAYS GOOD,
AND EVERYTHING'S JUST GREAT.
WHEN YOU SEE TEXAS BARBEQUE,
AND YOU HAVE YOUR FAVORITE JOINT
THAT YOU LIKE TO GO TO,
USUALLY IT'S A SMALL
LITTLE BARBEQUE SHACK WITH
ONE GUY COOKING ON ONE PIT,
BUT THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
BARBEQUE LAND.
IS THE BARBEQUE LEGIT?
IF IT AIN'T MINE,
I EAT HERE.
WHEN WE SAY BARBEQUE, THIS
IS WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S SOUTH TEXAS
PERFECT BARBEQUE.
THIS IS GOOD STUFF.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU'RE DOING IT HERE.
YEAH.
GOT A LITTLE RIB, SOME SAUSAGE,
SOME TURKEY, JALAPEÑOS,
PICKLES AND EVERYTHING
LAID OUT ON A LITTLE PLATTER.
YEAH.
NOW WHAT IS THAT CALLED?
ERMA'S MIX.
ERMA'S MIX?
I WOULD BE ERMA.
YOU'RE ERMA? OH.
ALL RIGHT, I JUST GOT
PLAYED ON MY OWN SHOW.
NEXT UP...
IT'S THE JOINT, MAN,
ALWAYS SMOKIN'.
NEW ORLEANS.
WE'RE IN BARBEQUE
NO-MAN'S-LAND.
(man) THERE'S NO ONE
PARTICULAR STYLE.
SO THIS GUY CAME UP
WITH ONE OF HIS OWN.
THE SMOKY FLAVOR
MAKES ALL OF IT GOOD.
THAT IS
OFF THE HOOK.
WHEN YOU THINK NEW ORLEANS,
YOU THINK FOOD, RIGHT--
JAMBALAYA, GUMBO, BEIGNETS--
BUT DO YOU THINK BARBEQUE?
WELL, HERE IN THE NINTH WARD YOU
DO, 'CAUSE THEY'RE SMOKIN' IT
OUT BACK, OUTSIDE,
AT A PLACE CALLED THE JOINT.
WOW.
IT'S THE JOINT, MAN,
ALWAYS SMOKIN'.
I GOTTA GET MY MASK.
I SMELLED SOMETHING,
AND IT WAS JUST LIKE,
WE GOTTA GO OVER THERE.
TWO PORK PLATES.
JOSHUA.
Y'ALL ENJOY.
THE SMOKY FLAVOR
MAKES ALL OF IT GOOD.
THAT'S KILLER.
WE LOVE THEIR RIBS.
WE LOVE THE PULLED PORK.
(man) THE MEAT
IS SO TENDER.
THEY COOK THE BEST BARBEQUE
I'VE EVER EATEN ANYWHERE.
THE KIND PETE BREEN...
I GOT TWO PORK PLATES.
AND HIS WIFE JENNY...
DONALD?
WE'RE DOING
IN THEIR OWN BACKYARD.
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH TO SHARE
A BACKYARD WITH A GUY
WITH A BIG COMMERCIAL
BARREL SMOKER.
GIVING PETE
THE PERFECT OPPORTUNITY
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT HE LIKED
AND HOW TO DO IT BEST.
WE'RE IN BARBEQUE
NO-MAN'S-LAND IN NEW ORLEANS.
THERE'S NO
ONE PARTICULAR STYLE.
SO THEY PUT TOGETHER
A MIXTURE--
CAROLINA TANGY...
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE A VINEGAR
SAUCE, LIKE NORTH CAROLINA.
KANSAS CITY SWEET...
I LOVE IT 'CAUSE IT'S GOT
A DIFFERENT TASTE TO IT.
AND WHATEVER ELSE FEELS RIGHT.
THIS IS JUST A PETE DESIGN
METHOD AND STYLE.
TRIAL AND ERROR,
MY FRIEND.
YOU DESIGNED
YOUR OWN SMOKER?
THAT'S TRUE, YEAH.
WHO DID THE WELDING?
JOEY PIPES.
JOEY PIPES
IS HIS REAL NAME?
THAT'S HIS REAL NAME.
AND THIS IS
ACTUALLY A TRAILER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS HAS BEEN TO MEMPHIS.
IN MAY?
IN MAY.
WOW, AND WHAT KIND
OF TEMPERATURE WE RUNNING AT?
I MEAN, WE'RE ALWAYS
AIMING FOR ABOUT 225.
'CAUSE IT'S
THE LOW AND SLOW THING
THAT KEEPS EVERYTHING TENDER.
WHAT ARE
YOU HAVING, BROTHER?
PULLED PORK.
THAT JUST
ABOUT FALLS APART.
THE MEAT'S AWESOME. IT'S VERY
JUICY AND GOOD FLAVOR ON IT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE RUB
FOR THIS PORK BUTT.
TURBINADO SUGAR.
BECAUSE...
YOU GET MUCH BETTER
DISTRIBUTION.
AND I THINK IT MELTS
A LITTLE BIT SLOWER.
I THINK SO, TOO.
A LOT OF BLACK PEPPER.
PAPRIKA, SALT,
WE'RE GONNA DO
THAT SHAKE THING.
HOW LONG DO THE BUTTS
GO DOWN FOR?
BUTTS ARE 10 TO 12.
10 TO 12.
NOW WE'RE GOING
FOR STRONG FLAVORS HERE
'CAUSE THIS IS A BIG CUT OF MEAT
THAT'S GONNA BE ON THAT SMOKER
FOR A LONG TIME, AND THIS
SUGAR IS GONNA HELP MAKE
THAT NICE CRUST
THAT WE ALL LOVE SO MUCH.
AND YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
TO CULINARY SCHOOL?
NO.
IT SOUNDS LIKE
YOU'RE PRETTY WELL VERSED
IN THE WHOLE GIG
OF DOING THE FOOD BIZ.
WELL, IT'S JUST A MATTER
OF EVERY DAY FOR FOUR YEARS NOW.
MINING FOR GOLD
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
I'LL GET IT RIGHT UP
UNDERNEATH. THERE WE GO.
AT LEAST THAT'S NOT
FALL-OFF-THE-BONE TENDER.
LOOK AT IT.
IT'S LIKE PORK CONFIT.
THAT'S LIQUI-FAT
RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THAT GOOD SMOKE RING
THAT YOU GET IN THERE.
NICE SMOKE PENETRATION.
I GET JUST A REAL GOOD,
NATURAL PORK FLAVOR
BUT NOT OVERWHELMING
WITH THE SPICE.
CAN WE BREAK OUT
SOME SAUCE?
ABSOLUTELY.
HE'S MAKING IT TWO WAYS--
SWEET TOMATO BASED,
FEATURING ROOT BEER
AND HOT SAUCE...
IT'S VERY SMOOTH, VERY LIGHT.
IT'S REAL GOOD.
THAT IS OFF
THE HOOK. SERIOUSLY.
AND THE OTHER ONE'S
GONNA HAVE SOME BITE.
IT'S LIKE A NORTH CAROLINA STYLE
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR SAUCE.
ADD IN OUR SPICES
AND WHISK HER UP.
SO WE'RE NOT GONNA
COOK THIS AT ALL?
WE'RE NOT
GONNA COOK AT ALL.
BROWN SUGAR.
RIGHT OVER HERE.
BLACK PEPPER.
IT'S GURGLING.
CUP OF CAYENNE,
CUP OF SALT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S A GOOD RATIO.
THAT'S READY TO GO.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
EASTERN
NORTH CAROLINA STYLE.
MAN, WHAT A REAL NICE BALANCE--
AN ORCHESTRA OF FLAVOR.
YEAH, WE'RE TRYING TO...
YOU'RE LIKE CONDUCTOR PETE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHICH ONE I LIKE BETTER.
I GOTTA SERIOUSLY--
I GOTTA QUIT EATING THIS
OR I'M GONNA GO
INTO PORK BARBEQUE COMA.
HEY, LOOK,
DEFENSELESS PUPPIES.
I LIKE 'EM
BOTH AT ONCE.
JUST GET IN
THERE LIKE THAT
AND COME OVER THE TOP AGAIN
WITH SOME MORE LIKE THAT.
YOU GOT A LITTLE
BIT OF EVERYTHING.
SO BRING AN APPETITE
AND PACK A BELT.
LIKE ON THE CHICKEN,
THE SKIN AND THE FLAVOR'S
JUST PHENOMENAL.
(Guy) HOW'S THE BRISKET?
OH, IT'S AMAZING.
THE BEST THING
ON THE MENU IS?
PORK RIBS.
(various men) RIBS.
LOOK AT THE CRUSTY BARK
ON THAT BAD BOY.
MMM. IT'S NICE AND JUICY
AND TENDER ALL THE WAY DOWN.
ME LIKE.
I USUALLY GO JUST
FOR THEIR RIBS,
BUT TODAY I DECIDED
TO MIX IT UP.
WHAT SIDE
WOULD YOU LIKE?
(Pete) SLAW, GREEN SALAD
AND BEANS.
THEIR COLESLAW
AND POTATO SALAD ARE THE BEST.
(man) THE BEANS
ARE FANTASTIC.
THE MAC AND CHEESE
IS PROBABLY MY FAVORITE
IN THE CITY--NICE AND SPICY.
TWO GREEN SALADS, PLEASE.
AND WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU WENT TO
A BARBEQUE JOINT FOR THIS?
I LOVE MESCLUN GREENS,
AND THE DRESSING
IS DEFINITELY HOMEMADE.
IT'S GOT A REALLY
KIND OF SMOKY FLAVOR TO IT.
'CAUSE EVEN THAT
STARTS IN THE SMOKER.
WHAT'S UP IN HERE?
THAT IS TOMATOES
AND ONIONS
FOR THE SMOKED TOMATO-ONION
SALAD DRESSING.
OH.
YOU GOT ME AT HELLO ON THIS ONE.
OKAY. I'M GONNA OPEN AND RUN.
ALL RIGHT. SLIDE 'EM IN.
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE 'EM
FOR AT LEAST AN HOUR.
WOW, THOSE
ARE NICE AND HOT.
THEN YOU'RE JUST GONNA GENTLY
PEEL THESE SKINS BACK.
NICE 225 DEGREE TOMATO...
MM-HMM.
ONIONS--PEEL
THE LITTLE OUTER LAYER OFF.
THAT'S THE RATIO--
A BUNCH TO SOME ONION?
YEAH, A BUNCH
OF SOME ONION.
OKAY.
WATCH FOR SPLASH FACTOR.
2 CUPS MAYO, BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE SEASON SALT.
THEN WE'LL GIVE IT
ANOTHER LITTLE SPIN.
WHO MADE UP THE RECIPE?
ME. I JUST KIND OF CAME
UP WITH IT.
WE HAVE A NICE
ORGANIC MIXTURE OF GREENS
AND RATHER THAN BUYING ALL
THE OTHER INGREDIENTS,
WE'LL JUST MAKE
A SALAD DRESSING OUT OF IT.
NICE.
THE FLAVOR'S GOTTA BE JUST
DYNAMITE ON THE BABY GREENS.
MMM. NICE, SMOKY FLAVOR--
NOT TOO MUCH SMOKE.
MMM. YOU GOT YOURSELF
SOMETHING THERE.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S TASTY.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE DRESSING IS DEFINITELY
HOMEMADE. IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT FITS RIGHT IN
WITH EVERYTHING ELSE.
THE COMMON THREAD IN
ALL THE FOOD IS THE SMOKER.
QUARTER CHICKEN, WHITE MEAT,
GREEN SALAD AND BEANS
IS READY TO GO, JENNY.
EXCUSE ME, PLEASE.
I LOVE THE SMOKE FLAVOR.
I CAN STILL TASTE THE MEAT.
I LOVE IT.
I'M ORIGINALLY FROM TEXAS.
IT'S MY FAVORITE PLACE
TO COME EAT BARBEQUE.
(man) FAVORITE PLACE
IN THE CITY.
WELL, YOU'VE GOT SOME BIG PLACES
TO BE SAYING FAVORITE PLACE.
WE ALSO LOVE
JENNY AND PETE.
HEY...
THEY'RE WARM,
AND THEY'RE SWEET.
IT JUST FEELS LIKE A JOINT.
THE NAME FITS REALLY WELL.
ALL RIGHTY, SAM.
DO Y'ALL COME HERE JUST FOR THE
GREAT OUTDOOR PATIO AMBIENCE,
OR DO YOU REALLY
LIKE THE FOOD?
FOOD'S ALL RIGHT.
WELL, 2 GALLONS OF THAT,
6 GALLONS OF THAT,
400 POUNDS OF THIS,
THE BEATLES "WHITE ALBUM"--
I WANT THAT IN
THE BACK OF MY CAMARO
WHEN I GET
READY TO LEAVE.
NEXT UP...
HOT BARBEQUE!
WE'RE HEADING
TO MISSISSIPPI...
MONEY, HONEY.
MONEY, HONEY!
WHERE THEY LIKE IT SWEET.
I'M OVER HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S 150 POUNDS
OF SUGAR.
YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE D
HOW WE'RE ALWAYS LOOKING
FOR THE ULTIMATE DIVE?
WELL, HERE I AM
IN OCEAN SPRINGS, MISSISSIPPI,
AND GUESS WHAT?
I THINK WE FOUND ONE.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THIS PLACE--
NICE FLOWER BED,
A LITTLE PIANO IN THE LOBBY,
BUT THEY NAMED THE PLACE RIGHT.
THEY CALL IT THE SHED.
PEOPLE AROUND HERE SAY THEY'VE
GOT SOME RIGHTEOUS BARBEQUE.
WHOO! FRESH BARBEQUE!
IT'S FANTASTIC.
STACY!
BRING IT ON.
FRESH Q.
THEIR OWN TAKE
ON MISSISSIPPI SWEET.
WE LIKE IT SWEET
HERE DOWN ON THE COAST.
YOU LIKE IT SWEET.
HOW MUCH SUGAR ARE YOU
GONNA PUT IN THIS THING?
ALWAYS MAKE IT
FROM SCRATCH.
FROM THE LOCAL
FAVORITE SAUCE...
THICK AND SWEET.
ARTHUR!
TO CLASSICS LIKE BRISKET...
BETTER THAN
ANY OTHER BARBEQUE PLACE.
AND PULLED PORK.
VERY TENDER, JUICY.
WINGS.
WHOO! THAT'S
GONNA COME OUT.
AH, THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
JASON!
AND THEIR TOP SELLER...
LOOK AT THAT
FULL RACK PLATE.
ABOUT AS TENDER
AS YOU GET.
THE RIBS IS MY FAVORITE,
THE BABY BACK RIBS.
THEY JUST FALL
OFF THE BONE.
(man) TWO BABY BACKS!
IT'S SO GOOD.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO DO BARBEQUE?
FROM MY DAD. WE'VE BEEN
RAISED ON THE GRILL.
AND ON THIS
PIECE OF LAND...
YAY!
WHERE BRAD ORRISON...
IT'S READY TO GO!
AND HIS SISTER
BROOKE LEWIS GREW UP.
THIS WAS THE PATIO
TO THE DOUBLE-WIDE?
EXACTLY.
WHO CAME UP
WITH THE NAME SHED?
IT'S WHAT I PUT
ON MY BUILDING PERMIT,
THAT I WAS GONNA BUILD
A STORAGE SHED.
ONLY THIS ONE
SERVED BARBEQUE.
CAN'T KEEP IT CLOSED!
TOO BIG OF A PLATE!
AND AFTER SIX YEARS, THE SHED'S
DOING BARBEQUE BY THE TON...
LUTHER!
AND DOING IT THEIR WAY.
WE DON'T USE
A BOWL AROUND HERE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME RUB?
WE'RE GONNA
MAKE SOME RIB RUB.
START IT OFF WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC SALT, CUMIN,
BLACK PEPPER, PAPRIKA...
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKING PAPRIKA.
CHILI POWDER, OREGANO.
YEP, A LITTLE BIT
OF WHITE PEPPER.
ALL RIGHT, NOW
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP.
PRETTY THOROUGH MIXING.
I MIGHT BE ADOPTING THAT ONE.
BROWN SUGAR.
SO ALL YOUR FAMILY OWNS
A SUGAR PLANTATION?
WE'LL BREAK UP
THE BROWN SUGAR A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP,
AND THAT'S A HEAVY ONE, THOUGH.
LOOK AT THAT. SO
WE'RE GOING BABY BACKS.
BABY BACK, BONE UP.
YOU DO THE BACK.
I LIKE THAT.
THEN WE'RE
GONNA ROLL 'EM.
YOU'RE GENEROUS
ON THE RUB.
GOTTA KEEP 'EM SWEET.
THESE ARE GONNA GO
IN THE SMOKER FOR HOW LONG?
TWO HOURS,
THEN WE TAKE 'EM OUT.
BUT THEY'RE NOT DONE YET.
BRAD WANTS 'EM EVEN SWEETER
AND MORE TENDER.
MORE RUB
JUST ON THE TOP.
SAUCE KIND OF LIKE CARAMEL,
THEN WE'LL WRAP 'EM.
SO NOW THESE GO
BACK IN THE OVEN?
YEP, FOR ANOTHER
TWO HOURS.
BUT YOU WRAPPED 'EM, SO THEY'RE
NOT GETTING ANY MORE SMOKE.
THEY'RE JUST GETTING HEAT.
RIGHT. TAKE 'EM
OUT OF THE SMOKER.
THEY JUST FALL
RIGHT APART, HUH?
THAT'S THE WAY
WE DO IT.
ABOUT AS TENDER AS YOU GET,
AND FOR PEOPLE WHO DON'T LIKE
TO PUT SAUCE ON THE RIBS, THIS
WOULD BE THEIR STYLE RIGHT HERE.
GOOD STUFF.
ANOTHER SOUVENIR.
BABY BACK DEMO.
THEY'RE EXTREMELY TENDER.
YOU CAN'T EAT 'EM ON THE BONE
'CAUSE THEY FALL OFF.
IF YOU TRY
TO PICK THE BONE UP,
ALL YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
IN YOUR HAND IS THE BONE.
SO WHAT IS THE BEST
THING ON THE MENU?
I LOVE THE BABY BACKS,
AND I LOVE THE SAUSAGE.
WHOA, NO ONE TOLD
ME ABOUT ANY SAUSAGE.
WHERE YOU AT
ON THAT, "B-RAD?"
TRY THAT OUT.
MMM. THAT SAUSAGE IS MONEY.
PUT THAT IN THE CAR.
THE SAUSAGE IS GOOD.
THE BRISKET'S GOOD.
TWO HALF-POUND
BRISKET SANDWICHES.
THE BRISKET'S MY FAVORITE.
(man) THAT IS TENDER.
BRISKET SANDWICH?
BEEF, BEEF.
BEEF, BEEF, BEEF.
NOT TOO SWEET EITHER.
NICE FEED.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
THE SAUCE. THE SAUCE
IS PROBABLY THE BEST.
SWEET MISSISSIPPI
BARBEQUE SAUCE.
WE CALL IT
POPPA JACK'S SHED SPREAD.
WITH GOOD REASON.
WE USED TO BUY IT IN 1-GALLON
BATCHES FROM PAPA JACK.
WHO TAUGHT BRAD EVERYTHING
HE KNEW ABOUT MAKING SAUCE.
NOW POPPA JACK
PASSED AWAY?
EVERY TIME I MAKE THIS SAUCE,
I'M MAKING THAT LEGEND LIVE.
HERE WE GO--SAUCE...
PASTE.
THIS IS THE KETCHUP
THAT'S GOING IN.
WE READY FOR THIS?
NOW MISSISSIPPI SAUCE
IS SWEET,
BUT THIS ONE'S
EVEN SWEETER THAN MOST.
HOW MUCH SUGAR YOU
GONNA PUT IN THIS THING?
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S 150 POUNDS.
THAT'S 150 POUNDS
OF SUGAR.
THAT'S ALL THE PEPPER THAT'S
GOING INTO 150 POUNDS OF SUGAR?
YES, SIR.
CAJUN SEASON SALT...
CAYENNE...
DRY MUSTARD.
NICE.
TURMERIC.
AND WITH ONION AND GARLIC SALT,
MUSTARD AND HOT SAUCE,
NOT EVERYTHING'S SWEET.
THAT IS NOT GONNA MAKE A DENT
IN 150 POUNDS OF SUGAR.
KITCHEN BOUQUET.
AND EVEN MORE--
LIQUID SMOKE, WORCESTERSHIRE,
SOY SAUCE,
BUT THEN AGAIN...
IT'S MORE SWEET.
CANE SYRUP--
'CAUSE THAT'S NEEDED.
YES, SIR.
YOU USE THIS
IN THE COOKING?
YES, SIR. POPPA JACK
ALWAYS HAD THE PADDLE.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK FOR?
IT'S GONNA GO
FOR AN HOUR.
NOW YOU'VE WON COMPETITIONS
WITH THIS SAUCE?
YEAH, WE TOOK FIRST PLACE
OUT OF 100.
I MEAN,
IT IS VERY SWEET,
BUT THERE IS
GOOD SPICE IN THERE.
GET A LITTLE BIT
ON THE TONGUE.
THE SAUCE IS INCREDIBLE.
YOU LIKE
THE SWEET SAUCE?
OH, YEAH.
IT IS PHENOMENAL.
(Brad) SAUCING 'EM UP,
SAUCING EM UP.
ABOUT 70 GALLONS A DAY
ON THE RIBS, BRISKET AND PORK.
DO YOU DO A SPICY?
HOT BARBEQUE!
WE DO A SPICY.
FORTIFY THE ONE
YOU ALREADY MADE?
YEP.
THAT'S THE ONE MOST FOLKS
WANT ON THE WINGS.
LOOK AT THEM.
(man) WHOO!
AND THE RUB...
LET ME GUESS--
BROWN SUGAR?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
GREEK SEASONING.
THEN MEW MEXICO
HOT CHILI POWDER.
YOU'RE KIND OF MULTICULTURAL
HERE WITH THIS ONE.
HOW LONG?
WE'RE GONNA DO THESE
ABOUT 2 1/2, 3 HOURS.
THAT'S A SMALL TURKEY.
OKAY, SO THEY'RE KIND OF TENDER
EVEN THE BONE BREAKS IN HALF.
THERE YOU GO.
TASTY. REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
I THINK PEOPLE DIG THESE.
THEY MUST LOVE 'EM.
YEP.
THEY'RE JUST SWEET,
THEY'RE GOOD,
AND IT'S JUST HOME-COOKED FOOD,
AND YOU CAN TELL IT.
EVERYTHING'S VERY FRESH.
THE COLESLAW'S GOOD.
BAKED BEANS--VERY GOOD.
THEY GET G'MAW'S BEANS
AND MAMA MIA'S MAC SALAD.
IT'S A FAMILY TRADITION
COMING UP.
THAT RIGHT THERE
IS SOME MONEY MAC.
MONEY, HONEY.
MONEY, HONEY!
(Brad) FRESH BARBEQUE!
MARTIN!
AT THE SHED
IN OCEAN SPRINGS, MISSISSIPPI,
THEY'RE MAKING BARBEQUE
THE WAY FOLKS AROUND HERE
HAVE BEEN LOVING IT FOREVER.
(Brad) SWEET SPICE.
HOT BARBEQUE!
BRAD ORRISON...
COMIN' ON DOWN!
AND HIS SISTER BROOKE LEWIS
HAVE 'EM LINING UP FOR
EVERYTHING FROM BRISKET
TO PORK
TO THE SHED SPECIALTY...
(Brad) FULL RACK
OF BABY BACKS!
BEANS...
WITH ALL KINDS
OF HOMEMADE SIDES.
PASTA SALAD BY FAR.
IT'S THE BEST.
OH!
THE FAVORITE IS
MAMA MIA'S MAC SALAD.
IT'S OUR MOM'S RECIPE.
AND YOU USE
A SHELL PASTA?
WE DO.
DO YOU EVER GET CAUGHT
WHEN YOU'RE BACK HERE
JUST BY YOURSELF
MAKING IT...
HUH? YOU EVER DO IT?
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
YEAH, I KNOW
YOU DO.
WHAT WE GOT HERE IS
WE GOT THE MAYONNAISE.
OKAY, YOU DONE? NOW WE'RE
GONNA START THE SOUR CREAM.
DO YOU WANT TO PLAY WITH THAT
FIRST BEFORE I POUR IT IN THERE?
DO A... ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA POUR
A LITTLE SOUR CREAM IN HERE.
SOME CIDER VINEGAR,
THEN WE'VE GOT SOME...
SUGAR!
PEPPER...
ONION POWDER, SALT,
GARLIC SALT, DIJON MUSTARD.
THE JUICE IS DONE,
MAMA MIA'S JUICE.
YOU CALL THIS THE JUICE?
THE JUICE.
LOOKS LIKE CEMENT.
COME ON.
LET ME DO IT RIGHT.
THERE WE GO.
I JUST SCOOP IT OUT
WITH MY HAND?
YOU CAN,
BUT I'D RATHER DO IT
WITH ONE OF THESE
LITTLE PUPPIES RIGHT HERE.
BELL PEPPERS, RED ONIONS.
OKAY, SO
A LITTLE CHEESE.
NOW THE FUN PART.
I'M JUST GONNA STIR HER UP.
LET'S EAT RIGHT OUT OF THE TUB.
NO DOUBLE-DIPPING.
NO, THAT'S ALL RIGHT. I HAVE
TO GET A MONGO FORK THEN.
MMM.
CREAMY, TANGY. DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT IT THE BEST?
GREEN BELL PEPPER--REAL NICE,
FRESH HERBACEOUS FLAVOR
AND THAT LITTLE CRUNCH
OF THE ONION.
OH, AND A FRESH FORK.
YOU WANT TO JUST OPEN YOUR
MOUTH? I'LL POUR IT IN.
...THROUGH SO MUCH OF IT--
I KNEW YOU WERE GONNA DO THAT!
I SAW YOU EYEIN'
MY MAC.
I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA.
IT'S GOOD.
I'M A MAC SALAD
AFICIONADO.
THAT RIGHT THERE IS
SOME MONEY MAC. IT'S GREAT.
PASTA SALAD--IT'S THE BEST.
IT'S THE BEST.
OH. THAT IS MONEY,
ISN'T IT?
IT IS.
DO YOU USE
THAT TERM A LOT?
YEAH.
I LIKE MONEY.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S EVERYTHING. IT'S GOT
THAT HOME-COOKING TASTE.
TINA!
WHY DO YOU ALL
COME HERE?
DELICIOUS BARBEQUE.
FUN.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
GETTIN' YOUR HEAD FED
AT THE SHED!
YOU'RE LOCATED ON...
HIGHWAY 57, BARBEQUE HEAVEN.
THAT'S IT.
SO WAS THAT A MONEY
ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DO YOU KNOW
HOW TO JUGGLE?
NO.
I'LL SHOW YOU
AS MUCH AS I KNOW.
HUH?
ARE WE THERE YET?
NOPE.
LOST THE REST
OF THE CREW.