HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(man) ALL RIGHT, WHAT DO
WE GOT COMIN' OUT NEXT?
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THIS IS WHAT DRIVE-INS
ALWAYS WERE.
AMERICAN CLASSICS...
WHO GETS THE, UH,
CHEESESTEAK?
(man) TURKEY DINNER'S UP.
A 60-YEAR-OLD
PENNSYLVANIA DINER...
HOW YOU GUYS DOIN'?
THEY MOVED TO MIAMI...
NOT YOUR TYPICAL
SOUTH BEACH DIET.
BON APPETIT.
(Guy) DID YOU JUST
THROW ME A "BON APPETIT?
AND YOU NEVER KNOW
WHO YOU'LL RUN INTO...
THERE'S JUST SOMETHIN'
ABOUT THIS PLACE
THAT FEELS LIKE HOME TO ME.
ORDER UP!
IN MEMPHIS, A 90-YEAR-OLD
SOUTHERN TEA ROOM...
(woman) YOU SEE THE SAME PEOPLE
SITTIN' AT THE SAME TABLE,
THE SAME AREAS EVERY DAY.
WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
A LOT MORE THAN LIPTON...
I CAN'T STOP EATIN' IT.
AND A KANSAS DRIVE-IN
STRAIGHT FROM THE '50s...
WE USED TO COME DOWN HERE
AND EAT ALL THE TIME
WHEN I WAS A KID.
AND STRAIGHT TO YOUR CAR...
HERE YOU GO.
FOR BURGERS...
MMM, THAT'S GOOD
CHEESEBURGER.
SHAKES AND HOMEMADE
APPLE PIE.
GO! THIS IS VICIOUS!
(cheering)
OH, EVERYBODY'S
A WINNER AT BOBO'S,
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
HERE IN FLORIDA, SOUTH BEACH
IS AN AMERICAN CLASSIC--
THE ART DECO BUILDINGS,
THE PALM TREES,
AND A FEW BLOCKS AWAY FROM HERE
IS ANOTHER AMERICAN CLASSIC.
BUILT IN '48 AND SHIPPED DOWN
FROM PENNSYLVANIA,
THEY'RE DOIN' THE DINER THING
HERE SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
WELCOME
TO THE 11th STREET DINER.
(Guy) OH, WOW.
(man) TURKEY DINNER'S UP.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
THIS IS A GREAT PLACE
TO HAVE SOME GOOD FOOD.
WHO GETS THE, UH,
CHEESESTEAK?
NOT YOUR TYPICAL
SOUTH BEACH DIET HERE.
(man) ALL RIGHT, WHAT DO
WE GOT COMIN' OUT NEXT?
YOU GOT YOUR
COMFORT FOOD,
AND YOUR BURGERS
ARE FANTASTIC.
OH! I WANT THAT
FOR CHRISTMAS DINNER.
(man) PANCAKES UP.
VERY UNUSUAL TO FIND
A DINER LIKE THIS IN MIAMI.
(man) WOW, THIS
LOOKS GREAT.
11th STREET DINER.
JUST THE KIND OF JOINT EAST-
COAST NATIVES RAY SCHNITZER...
WE GOT A COUPLE
SPECIALS TONIGHT.
AND HIS BROTHER STEVEN...
ALL RIGHT, HAVE
A GOOD ONE.
GREW UP ON.
THAT THING LOOKS GOOD.
WELL, WE GREW UP BEING ABLE
TO GO OUT AT MIDNIGHT
OR 2:00 IN THE MORNING--
BE ABLE TO GO TO THE DINER
AND HAVE SOMETHING TO EAT.
43 JUST WENT OUT.
SOMETHING THEY COULDN'T GET
WHEN THEY ENDED UP
IN SOUTH BEACH.
AND THIS WAS
A VACANT LOT.
I SAID, "THIS WOULD BE A GREAT
PLACE TO HAVE A DINER."
SO THEY HAULED DOWN A 1948
MODEL FROM PENNSYLVANIA...
A REAL DINER.
LIKE YOU WOULD FIND IN--
NEW YORK.
WITH A CLASSIC MENU.
THE EVERYTHING BURGER-
IT'S AWESOME.
THE PATTY MELT, HOT TURKEY
SANDWICH AND THE MONTE CRISTO.
FILL-YOU-UP, COMFORT
KIND OF FOOD.
VERY AMERICAN-CLASSIC
DINER.
BUT THEY'RE DOIN' IT
WITH A SOUTH BEACH TWIST.
BODY BUILDER'S--THE THING HAS
GOT, LIKE, TEN EGG WHITES IN IT.
THERE'S AN ATLANTIC
SALMON SPECIAL
WITH A BLUE CRAB STUFFING,
AND JUST LOOK
HOW THEY'RE TREATIN'
THE CLASSIC PORK CHOP.
WE HAVE THE APPLE-RAISIN
PORK CHOPS HERE.
IT'S GOT APPLES AND RAISINS.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
A FRESH APPLE.
THIS IS
THE PORK CHOP SAUCE?
YES.
INVENTED BY A LONGTIME
COOK HERE, JEAN LYSIUS.
RAISINS AND BROWN SUGAR.
OKAY.
LET IT MARINATE
OVERNIGHT.
AND SO A LITTLE
BUTTER GOES DOWN?
(Jean) GO AHEAD.
YOU GOT SOME
FRESH DEMI-GLACE.
DEMI-GLACE?
YEAH.
THIS IS A LITTLE STRANGE.
IT'S GONNA BE TASTY.
AND THAT GOES OVER
THE GRILLED PORK CHOP.
PORK CHOP.
CENTER CUT CHOPS, BONE ON,
SALT AND WHITE PEPPER.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE BIT ON TOP.
THIS IS A CORN FLOUR MIX.
AND THIS IS JUST
THE GARNISH?
THIS IS JUST
THE GARNISH.
HAVE YOU SEEN HOW BUSY
IT IS OUT THERE?
THIS IS NOT, LIKE, TIME
TO BE MESSIN' AROUND
WITH FRIED APPLE
GARNISH.
KIND OF, LIKE,
SET 'EM UP.
OH!
THIS IS IT
RIGHT HERE, BABY.
IT'S LIKE FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
INSTEAD, IT'S BIG RED APPLES.
BON APPETIT.
DID YOU JUST THROW ME
A BON APPETIT?
YEAH.
THERE IS SO MUCH FLAVOR
GOIN' ON
INSIDE OF THIS--
THIS APPLE GRAVY THING.
LOOK AT THAT.
AHH!
SAVORY AND SWEET.
AND YOU GUYS MAKE
THE MAC AND CHEESE, TOO?
WE MAKE--
WE MAKE THE MAC AND CHEESE.
THAT'S ABOUT ALL-AMERICAN
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOIN' ACROSS THE WATER
WITH RICE AND BEANS.
(mumbles) NOW I'M GOIN'
ACROSS THE WATER?
LISTEN TO HIM.
HUH.
(normal voice)
I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA.
THAT'S GOT TO BE UP THERE WITH
ONE OF THE BEST PORK CHOP DISHES
I'VE HAD ON TRIPLE-D.
I'M SLOBBERIN'
AS I SAY IT.
I APPRECIATE IT.
THE RAISINS, THE APPLES
ARE JUST WONDERFUL.
THEY'RE EXQUISITE.
HOW YOU LIKE
THESE APPLES?
OR THESE PEARS WITH WALNUTS,
GORGONZOLA,
AND A SCRATCH-MADE
CITRUS DRESSING?
THERE'S A CALIFORNIA
CHICKEN SANDWICH
WITH PEPPERS, MUSHROOMS, ONIONS
AND MOZZARELLA CHEESE.
YOUR STEAK.
THEY'RE GOIN' WAY SOUTH
OF THE BORDER FOR THIS ONE.
ARGENTINEAN STEAK.
WITH, UM,
CHIMICHURRI RELISH.
VERY NICE.
ARGENTINA STEAK?
YEAH.
SO WE GOT OLIVE OIL,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE BAY LEAF,
GARLIC POWDER,
WHITE PEPPER, CAYENNE PEPPER,
COARSE BLACK PEPPER.
A LOT OF PEPPER.
YEAH, A LOT OF PEPPER.
GOT A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
WE JUST GET OUR STEAK
AND LET 'EM MARINATE
IN THERE OVERNIGHT.
SO AFTER IT
MARINATES NOW,
DOES IT GET GRILLED?
IT GETS GRILLED.
WE ACTUALLY HAVE
A HOMEMADE CHIMICHURRI
THAT WE PUT RIGHT
ON TOP OF IT.
IT'S AN ARGENTINEAN
SALSA.
PRETTY MUCH. FRESH GARLIC.
FRESH PARSLEY.
CHOPPED TOMATOES.
RED WINE VINEGAR.
VIRGIN OLIVE OIL
AND A TAP OF SALT.
WE MAKE IT BY THE ORDER.
OH, REALLY?
YEAH, WHILE THE STEAK
IS COOKING.
EVERY TIME
AN ORDER COMES IN?
YEAH, 'CAUSE WE'RE LIKE,
"YO, I NEED A SALSA,"
AND THEY'LL WHIP IT UP
RIGHT QUICK AND JUST PUT IT
RIGHT ON THE PLATE.
"WHIP IT UP
RIGHT QUICK?"
YES.
LOOK AT ALL THAT
ON THERE.
MMM.
SKIRT STEAK IS THE BEST
TO DO GRILLED
AND PUT THAT LITTLE BIT
OF CRUST ON THERE,
AND IT GETS NICE
AND JUICY.
AND THAT CHIMICHURRI,
BECAUSE OF THOSE BOLD FLAVORS--
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
ANYTIME YOU COME IN,
YOU COULD GET IT.
ANY TIME OF THE DAY?
ANY TIME OF THE DAY.
ARGENTINA STEAK
IN THE MORNING.
I MEAN,
COULDN'T BE BETTER.
OR PANCAKES FOR DINNER.
(man) ONE MORE
PANCAKES UP.
ALMOST ANYTHING...
GRILLED MAHI SANDWICH.
AT ANY TIME...
WILL YOU HAND ME
THE GRITS, PLEASE?
FOR A CROWD OF BOTH
OUT-OF-TOWNERS
AND ROUND-THE-CLOCK
REGULARS...
IT MAKES YOU FEEL
REALLY GOOD.
THAT EVEN INCLUDES
ROSIE O'DONNELL.
SO, ROSIE, HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN COMIN' HERE?
SINCE 1994.
AND TODAY,
SHE DROPPED IN FOR LUNCH.
A GOOD DINER--
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT.
YOU COME IN HERE IN, UH,
THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
IT'S JUST AS CROWDED.
YOU GET CHEESEBURGER
DELUXE AT 3:00 A.M.
ROASTED TURKEY DINNER.
OR A FRESH
THANKSGIVING DINNER
ANY DAY OF ANY WEEK.
TWO TURKEY A DAY.
EVERY DAY,
YOU MAKE TURKEYS?
EVERY DAY.
A LITTLE CHICKEN BASE.
SEASONED SALT.
ONION POWDER.
THIS IS GARLIC
POWDER.
GARLIC POWDER.
COME ON, I CAN PLAY
ON THE TEAM.
OH, THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
PUT THAT ON.
IT'S THE DRY RUB.
GET A LITTLE WATER?
GET IT NICE AND MOIST.
I START IT OFF AT 350.
IN TWO HOURS,
WE TAKE OFF THE FOIL
AND JUST LET IT--
LET IT SIT THERE
AND BROWN THE TOP?
YES.
HOW OFTEN DO WE
MAKE THE STUFFING?
UH, EVERY DAY.
DAILY.
BUTTER, ONIONS, CELERY.
CELERY.
OH, IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE
PARTS OF STUFFING.
FRESH THYME.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE GARLIC.
A LITTLE CHICKEN BASE
GOES DOWN?
TURKEY BASE DOWN.
SALT, A LITTLE WATER.
WELL, WE GOT OURSELVES
THE BEGINNING OF A NICE SOUP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE USE FRESH BREAD
EVERY DAY.
SOME CORN BREAD?
LOOK AT THAT.
KEEP STIRRIN' IT TILL IT
GETS NICE AND MOIST.
I AM STIRRIN' IT!
KEEP ON STIRRIN'.
SMELLS KILLER.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT, TOO?
YOU LET IT SIT OUT
FOR WHAT?
20 MINUTES BEFORE YOU
SLICE INTO IT?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES, YEAH.
ONE SCOOP?
ONE SCOOP.
MMM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
WE NEED A SLICE OF THAT.
I GET THAT DRY RUB.
NICE FLAVORS IN THAT.
MMM, THAT'S NICE STUFF THERE.
GOT REALLY GOOD
TEXTURE TO IT.
THIS IS A LEGIT
THANKSGIVING DINNER.
MMM, GOOD LOOKIN' OUT,
MAN.
REAL DEAL RIGHT THERE.
I EAT TURKEY EVERY DAY
'CAUSE IT'S FRESH
OFF THE BIRD.
YOU'RE GONNA FIND
MAMA'S HOME COOKIN'.
AND IT TASTES JUST AS GOOD
IF NOT BETTER.
(man) TWO OVER-MEDIUM,
PLEASE.
SORRY, MOM.
WHO GETS
THE FISH SANDWICH?
RIGHT HERE.
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS PLACE
THAT FEELS LIKE HOME
TO ME.
(woman) EVERYBODY
IS REALLY SWEET.
YOU KNOW EVERYBODY, 'CAUSE MOST
OF 'EM ARE ALL LOCALS.
LOOK FOR THE OLD-FASHIONED
DINER WITH THE UNUSUAL MENU.
DINERS, DUMPS AND DRIVES...
DISCOS.
AND DISCOS.
DUNKIN' DONUTS AND DOGS.
PEACE OUT.
COMIN' UP,
A MEMPHIS LANDMARK...
OH!
WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
CLASSIC SOUTHERN COOKIN'...
ALL SOUTHERN FOOD,
AND IT IS EXCELLENT.
WITH A NOT-SO-SOUTHERN TWIST.
THIS MIGHT BE
THE FIRST TIME
I'VE SEEN FRIED CHICKEN
AND ALLSPICE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S THE MIDDLE EASTERN
IN ME, DARLING.
THERE'S A KIND OF
CLASSIC AMERICAN JOINT
THAT'S YOU USED TO FIND
ALL OVER THE SOUTH.
IT WAS CALLED A TEA ROOM.
NOW THIS ONE HERE
OPENED IN MEMPHIS IN 1918,
AND THEY WERE SUPPOSED
TO BE A NICE, QUIET PLACE
FOR PROPER LADIES
TO ENJOY A LIGHT LUNCH.
NOW 90 YEARS LATER,
THIS ONE'S STILL SERVIN' LUNCH.
BUT IT'S NOT SO LIGHT,
AND IT'S NOT SO QUIET,
BECAUSE THE GUYS HAVE
DISCOVERED THE PLACE, TOO.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
THIS IS THE PLACE
TO GO TO?
ABSOLUTELY.
EVERYTHING OKAY HERE?
(woman) YOU SEE THE SAME PEOPLE
SITTIN' AT THE SAME TABLES
EVERY DAY.
IT'S JUST A GREAT
PLACE TO BE.
SWEET TEA.
(woman) EVERY TIME
YOU COME,
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA
GET A GOOD MEAL.
THIS IS AS GOOD
A CORNBREAD
AS YOU CAN GET ANYWHERE
IN THE WORLD RIGHT HERE.
LOVE THE TURNIP GREENS HERE.
THEY'RE THE BEST.
SCALLOPED TOMATO.
OH, THAT'S KILLER.
LOVE IT.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THERE'S SOUTHERN-FRIED CHICKEN,
CHICKEN PAN PIE,
MAC 'N' CHEESE,
FRIED OKRA AND SQUASH.
IT'S ALL SOUTHERN FOOD,
AND IT IS EXCELLENT.
ORDER UP!
AS FOR THE SOUTHERN COOK...
I SERVE CLASSIC FOOD.
SUHAIR LAUCK
GREW UP IN JERUSALEM
THEN MOVED TO MEMPHIS
AND LEARNED TO COOK
LIKE A LOCAL.
I LEARNED HOW TO DO IT
BY WATCHING,
AND THEN I ADDED
MY LITTLE ACCENT.
LIKE SOUTHERN-FRIED CHICKEN
WITH SOME MIDDLE EASTERN SPICE.
JUST GIVE IT A VERY
UNUSUAL FLAVOR.
A LITTLE SWEETER THAN
YOU NORMALLY WOULD FIND.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S NOT GREASY.
IT'S JUST THE BEST
FRIED CHICKEN.
SEE THE CHICKEN?
OKAY.
IT'S CUT IN QUARTERS,
SO WE CRACK THE EGG.
OKAY.
THEN I'M GONNA
PUT BUTTERMILK.
WOW, LOOK AT THIS.
BLACK PEPPER.
GARLIC.
SEASONED SALT.
MUSTARD.
A LITTLE BIT
OF PAPRIKA.
HOT SAUCE.
YOU DON'T MIX IT AHEAD OF
TIME AND THEN POUR IT IN?
NOPE. NOPE, EVERYTHING
LIKE THIS.
OKAY.
THIS IS CAJUN SEASONING.
JUST GIVE IT
A LITTLE KICK.
'CAUSE IT PROBABLY HAS
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
YES.
ALLSPICE. THAT'S THE MIDDLE
EASTERN IN ME, DARLING.
LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE
SAUCE, OKAY?
I LIKE THAT.
THAT DO WE GOT HERE?
A LITTLE ONION POWDER?
THIS IS ONION
THIS IS--I'M NOT GONNA
TELL YOU WHAT IT IS.
OH, I KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
I KNOW.
MMM.
OKAY.
CALL ME LATER,
I'LL TELL YOU.
IT'S OUR SECRET.
OKAY, MY HANDS CLEAN,
'CAUSE I STERILIZE THEM, LIKE--
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
ARE YOU GOIN'--
I'M GONNA GO IN
IT LIKE THAT.
THERE'S A WAY
THAT YOU COULD
JUST MIX ALL OF IT IN
THE CONTAINER AND THEN--
I CAN, BUT THIS
IS MORE FUN.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIT
THERE AND MARINATE?
JUST MAYBE AN HOUR
OR LESS.
OKAY, SO NOW WE DREDGE IT
IN A LITTLE BIT OF THE FLOUR.
THAT HAS SOME OF THE SAME
INGREDIENTS IN THERE.
YES.
AND THAT'S OUR CHICKEN.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
AND FRY IT.
SEE HOW PRETTY
AND CRISPY?
YES, IT IS
PRETTY AND CRISPY.
LOOK HOW STEAMING-HOT
THAT IS.
MMM, GOOD CRUNCH.
IT'S NOT OVERLY SPICY.
PICK UP A LITTLE BIT
OF THE, UM, ALLSPICE
AND A LITTLE BIT OF
THE BUTTERMILK RICHNESS.
YEP, YOU CAN TELL
I DIDN'T LIKE IT.
THAT'S GOOD CHICKEN.
NOW HOW DOES THIS FRIED
CHICKEN STACK UP?
WELL, YOU KNOW,
THERE'S SOME STIFF
COMPETITION,
BUT I'D SAY IT'S
JUST RIGHT ON TOP.
WELL, I DON'T HEAR
ANY COMPLAINTS.
ABOUT THE CHICKEN OR
THE OTHER SOUTHERN CLASSICS
DONE SUHAIR'S WAY,
LIKE HER LIGHTER TAKE
ON CORNBREAD--CORN STICKS...
WELL, THEY'RE
JUST FANTASTIC.
CORNMEAL?
CORNMEAL.
SCRATCH BAKED...
WHAT ARE THOSE THINGS?
IN THE SAME ANCIENT PANS
EVERY DAY.
(Suhair) ♪ TA-DA ♪
GREAT TEXTURE.
GREAT CRUNCH.
LITTLE SWEETNESS.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
I LOVE THIS.
NOW THE CORN STICKS
ARE ALWAYS AVAILABLE,
BUT A LOT OF THE MENU'S
DIFFERENT EACH DAY OF THE WEEK.
THANK YOU.
YOU DEAL WITH IT. IF THERE'S
SOMETHING YOU REALLY LIKE...
"YOU DEAL WITH IT."
YOU COME IN ON TUESDAY.
OR MONDAY, IF YOU WANT
SALMON CROQUETTES.
CHICKEN PAN PIE
IS ON THE FRIDAY MENU.
IT HAS A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYTHING IN IT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TUESDAY'S MENU INCLUDES
SUHAIR'S VERSION
OF A SOUTHERN CLASSIC CALLED
HOPPIN' JOHN.
HOPPIN' JOHN IS,
UH, BLACK-EYED PEAS...
BLACK-EYED PEAS,
RIGHT.
AND TURNIP GREENS
AND HAM HOCK.
BUT I DON'T LIKE THAT, SO I
SAID BEANS FROM THE MID-EAST.
AND THE NUMBER ONE LEGUME
IS THE LENTIL,
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO--
ONIONS.
CELERY.
I PUT PARSLEY. WE HAVE
ALL TYPES OF BELL PEPPERS,
'CAUSE IT'S GOOD FOR YOU
AND IT'S COLORFUL.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME SPICES.
CORIANDER.
ONION.
GARLIC--LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS ONE OF MY
SECRET INGREDIENTS.
CAN I SMELL?
MM-HMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS.
MMM!
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
BAY LEAVES. HOT SAUCE.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
BEEF STOCK.
SO I'M GONNA PUT
ALL THIS LIKE THAT.
AND WE'RE GONNA
GO TO THE STOVE.
EVERY--ALL RIGHT.
OHH!
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
ADD SPINACH.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
FRY CHOPPED ONIONS.
NOW ARE WE COOKING
THEM TRANSLUCENT?
OR ARE WE FRYING THEM?
NO, WE LIKE IT
A LITTLE BROWNER.
CARAMELIZED.
GONNA SQUEEZE THE--
THE LIME.
AND WE PUT LITTLE BIT
IN HERE.
NOW THE ROUX CAN GO IN?
YES.
AND YOU MAKE THAT ROUX
YOURSELF?
YES, SIR.
THE LITTLE GARLIC.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
NOT MUCH, OKAY?
YOU'LL EVEN NOTICE
THERE'S GARLIC IN THERE
AFTER THAT BIG
POT OF FLAVOR? OKAY.
I LIKE TO PUT AT
THE LAST MINUTE.
IT TASTES BETTER.
I BRING RICE PILAF.
(Suhair) THIS IS YOUR
CHANCE TO TASTE IT.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
YOU'RE VERY KIND.
OUTSTANDING.
THANK YOU, DARLING.
I CAN'T STOP
EATIN' IT.
THE LENTILS ARE
COOKED PERFECTLY.
MY MOM'S JUMPING UP
AND DOWN RIGHT NOW.
THAT HAS MORE GREENS
RIGHT THERE--
THAT'S MY MONTHLY INTAKE.
I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA.
THAT MIGHT BE UP THERE
WITH SOME OF THE BEST
THINGS I'VE EVER HAD.
I APPRECIATE IT.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SPICY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(woman) IT'S BETTER
THAN HOPPIN' JOHN.
AND I'M GONNA GET MY SOUTHERN
CARD TAKEN AWAY FROM ME.
NO, SHE WON'T.
ORDER UP.
'CAUSE WITH ALL OF SUHAIR'S
MIDDLE EASTERN SPIN,
SHE'S STILL RUNNIN'
A CLASSIC SOUTHERN TEA ROOM
FOR A SOUTHERN CROWD
THAT KNOWS WHEN IT'S RIGHT.
(woman) SHE'S COOKING
SOUTHERN FOOD
BETTER THAN MOST
SOUTHERNERS THAT I KNOW.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
HER SOUTHERN HOSPITALITY
IS WHY WE KEEP COMIN' BACK.
IT'S LIKE COMIN' TO SEE
YOUR FAMILY MEMBERS
WHEN YOU COME HERE.
IT'S BEEN
ABSOLUTELY AWESOME.
I HAVE A PARTY
EVERY DAY,
AND THAT'S WHAT I LOVE
ABOUT MY JOB.
GIVE ME FIVE.
I'D LOVE TO.
JUST KIDDING.
UP NEXT...
THAT'S GOOD EATS.
WE'RE DRIVING IN...
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
TO A KANSAS CLASSIC...
WE CAME HERE AS TEENAGERS,
AND WE COME BACK NOW.
WHERE THEY'RE DOIN' IT ALL...
(man) ORDER UP.
THEIR WAY.
I'M GONNA HAVE
A SPANISH BURGER
MADE BY A WOMAN
FROM ENGLAND...
THAT'S RIGHT.
IN KANSAS, SO IT'S KIND OF
LIKE THE U.N. OF FOOD.
YES.
ONE OF THE THINGS I LOVE
ABOUT TRIPLE-D
IS FINDING THE KIND OF PLACES
THAT BELONG TO THE WHOLE TOWN.
YOU KNOW,
THE KIND OF JOINTS
THAT FEEL LIKE THEY'VE
BEEN THERE FOREVER.
IN TOPEKA, KANSAS, THAT MEANS
A TRIP TO BOBO'S DRIVE-IN.
(man) CAR NUMBER SIX.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
WE CAME HERE AS TEENAGERS,
AND WE COME BACK NOW.
(man) UH, TWO CHEESEBURGERS
AND AN ONION RING.
THAT'S GOOD EATS.
REMINDS ME OF WHEN
I WAS A KID.
HI!
THIS WAS A BIG HANGOUT.
STILL IS...
THEY HAVEN'T CHANGED
THE MENU AT ALL.
FROM DOUBLE CHEESEBURGERS
TO CONEY DOGS
TO FRESH-CUT RINGS
MADE EVERY DAY.
THEY ARE SO GOOD.
ONE STRAWBERRY SHAKE,
PLEASE, FOR HERE.
THEY'VE GOT THE SWEET STUFF,
TOO...
THE CHOCOLATE MALTS
ARE TO DIE FOR.
AND CHECK THIS OUT--
AT A DRIVE-IN.
(woman) BOBO'S HOT APPLE PIE
WITH ICE CREAM.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
REALLY GOOD.
HERE YOU GO.
THIS IS WHAT DRIVE-INS
ALWAYS WERE.
LIKE BACK IN 1953
WHEN BOB BOBO STARTED SERVING
HIS AUNT AND MOM'S
ORIGINAL RECIPE.
ORDER UP.
RICHARD MARSH
AND HIS WIFE TRICIA...
WANT A REFILL?
BOUGHT THE PLACE
A YEAR AGO.
LET ME KNOW IF YOU
NEED ANYTHING ELSE.
MY BEST FRIEND'S
A COMMERCIAL REALTOR.
HE CONTACTED US
AND SAID,
"I FOUND THE PERFECT
THING FOR YOU."
HOW DID HE TALK YOU
INTO THIS IDEA?
I TALKED HIM
INTO THIS IDEA.
REALLY?
YEAH!
DESPITE A TOTAL LACK OF
EXPERIENCE IN THE FOOD BIZ
FOR BOTH OF THEM.
IT'S JUST A DREAM
COME TRUE FOR US.
YOU SEE, THEY DO HAVE
THE OLD BOBO RECIPES.
MEDIUM CHILI.
AND THE STAFF THAT'S BEEN
THE HEART OF THIS PLACE
FOR YEARS.
STARTED WORKING
HERE IN '68.
15 YEARS I'VE
BEEN MAKIN' THIS.
I'VE WORKED FOR BOBO'S
FOR 34 YEARS.
THEY WORK HERE 30 YEARS.
WE COME BACK FOR 30 YEARS.
SO YOU KNOW HOW IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE DONE.
OH, YEAH.
THERE'S TWO PATTIES
FOR A DOUBLE BURGER.
BETTY RAMSEY,
WHO MOVED HERE FROM ENGLAND,
HAS BEEN MAKING THESE
ALL-AMERICAN BURGERS SINCE '75.
EQUAL PRESSURE ON IT.
EQUAL PRESSURE SO
IT GOES DOWN FLAT.
BUT THAT'S--
THAT'S NICE AND THIN.
SO THEY COOK UP QUICK?
AHH, THERE WE GO.
SO A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER?
UH-HUH.
AND THEN WE PUT ON
A COUPLE OF BUNS.
OH-HO, AND THAT'S THE--
YOU HAVE TO GO AROUND.
THE WAY TO DO IT?
YEP.
LET ME SEE THOSE FOREARMS.
I BET YOU WE COULD
ARM WRESTLE FOR SOME--
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S A GOOD WORKOUT.
IS IT SUPPOSED TO GO ON
WITH THE PAPER?
YEAH.
I'VE NOT OFTEN
THROWN MY--
OH, THAT MAKES IT
COME OFF NICE.
MM-HMM. THERE'S YOUR
DOUBLE CHEESE.
IS THERE A SPECIAL WRAP?
YEAH.
OKAY.
GO AROUND LIKE THAT.
OVER, OVER, TWIST
AND FLIP.
AND THEN...
THAT'S TO SAY
IT'S A CHEESEBURGER
AND THAT SAYS
IT'S A DOUBLE.
MMM.
THAT'S GOOD CHEESEBURGER.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE
IS THE CRUST ON IT.
THE CRUST--THIS IS NUMBER ONE
ITEM THAT PEOPLE ORDER?
BY FAR, YEAH.
THE DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
BEST HAMBURGER IN TOWN.
TO DIE FOR.
(woman) THEY'RE REAL
CHEESEBURGERS,
BUT WE COME
FOR THE ONION RINGS.
THEY'RE JUST REALLY
CRISPY.
THEY MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
(Richard) ROUGHLY
75 POUNDS
OF ONIONS A DAY.
HOLY ONION RINGS,
BATMAN!
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME WHOLE MILK.
THEY'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A BATH IN THE MILK HERE.
DUMP 'EM IN THE FLOUR.
THIS IS WHAT SEPARATES
THE REAL ONION RING MAKER
FROM JUST THE AMATEUR, WHICH
IS HOW YOU SIFT THESE BABIES.
THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT.
NOW YOU GO OVER THERE.
AND THAT'S TO GET
THE EXCESS FLOUR OFF?
EXACTLY.
SHAKE, SHAKE, SHAKE.
IN THE POOL.
MAKE SURE
EVERYBODY'S WET.
AND THEN OVER INTO--
THE CRACKER MEAL.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
NOT TOO MUCH
BATTER.
WE WANT THE ONION
COMIN' THROUGH.
BUT NO SEASONING
ON 'EM?
IT'S JUST WHOLESOME ONION
AND CRACKER
AND MILK AND FLOUR.
ALM--PRACTICALLY
HEALTH FOOD.
WELL, YEAH,
EXCEPT FOR THAT SMALL
FRYING ASPECT.
AND THEY DUST 'EM
WITH SALT
WHEN THEY COME OUT
OF THE FRYER.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
GOTTA GET THE SALT ON 'EM
WHEN THAT GREASE IS HOT.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
GOTTA LIKE
THE ONION RINGS.
NICE AND CRUNCHY.
THEY'RE JUST THE BEST
ONION RINGS.
AND STILL...
(Richard) ONE RING.
HAND-DELIVERED.
YOU EVER FORGET THAT
THE TRAY IS ON THIS
AND ROLL DOWN THE WINDOW
OR HIT THE AUTOMATIC WINDOW
AND THINGS START GOIN'?
IT'S A TRADITION.
LIKE EVERYTHING HERE.
NOW THE CHILI--
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
THIS IS MR. BOBO'S
MOM AND AUNT.
MMM, PUT DOWN A BOWL
OR SIX OF THESE.
THAT MUST BE INSANE
ON A CHILI DOG.
OH, YEAH.
THAT IS GREAT.
SPANISH BURGER.
AND THEY'VE BEEN
MAKING THIS ONE
WITH THE SAME SAUCE
SINCE '53.
WE START WITH KETCHUP.
WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA
DO THREE OF 'EM.
MINCED ONIONS, SUGAR,
WHITE DISTILLED VINEGAR.
THE HOT--
OUR SECRET SPICE.
I GOT A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
LITTLE CAYENNE,
LITTLE--
SOME SEED IN THERE.
WOW, THAT'S
AN INTERESTING BLEND.
OUR EVER-IMPORTANT--
ONE SCOOP OF LARD.
NOW ANYTHING ELSE
GO IN THIS?
SPICE BALL.
CLOVES? NO.
STAR ANISE IS GOING--
ARE YOU SURE
THEY WEREN'T
MESSIN' WITH YOU?
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
WE'RE GONNA TIE IT UP
WITH A LITTLE TWINE.
JUST LIKE THAT.
SEE, I KNEW YOU WERE
GONNA THROW IT.
ONTO THE STOVE,
AND IT GOES DOWN,
AND IT COOKS
FOR 45 MINUTES.
RIGHT.
I'M GONNA HAVE A SPANISH BURGER
MADE BY A WOMAN FROM ENGLAND...
THAT'S RIGHT.
IN KANSAS.
INTERNATIONAL FLAVOR.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
THE U.N. OF FOOD.
YES.
THIS IS TASTY--
THE SPANISH SAUCE.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT
KIND OF REMINDS ME OF?
A SLOPPY JOE WITHOUT IT
BEING ALL GROUND UP.
THAT'S GOOD EATS.
THEY BRING IN
ALL THOSE NEW PLACES,
BUT THEY'RE NOT
LIKE BOBO'S.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
BUT THIS IS THE REAL SURPRISE.
I NEED A PIECE OF PIE.
OH, I GOTTA TRY PIE.
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, YES.
AT A DRIVE-IN?
HOMEMADE APPLE PIE
EVERYONE'S FALLING FOR.
GO!
(woman) GO, GO, GO!
GO, GO, GO!
IN TOPEKA, KANSAS, THE BOBO
DRIVE-IN IS A TRADITION...
WE USED TO COME DOWN HERE
TO EAT ALL THE TIME
WHEN I WAS A KID.
FOUR GENERATIONS.
(Guy) WE HAVE FOUR GENERATIONS
OF BOBO EATERS?
SINCE '53.
THEY'RE DOIN' ALL
THE DRIVE-IN CLASSICS...
ONE STRAWBERRY SHAKE,
PLEASE, FOR HERE.
AND HOME-MAKIN'
SOMETHING YOU JUST DON'T
SEE AT MOST DRIVE-INS.
THE APPLE PIE
IS TO DIE FOR.
'CAUSE NOBODY'S MAKIN' IT
LIKE JO MENDOZA.
MISS J., WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS THE APPLE PEELER.
FROM WHAT CENTURY?
OKAY, PRESS YOUR BUTTON.
MAKE SURE ALL MY CLOTHING'S
NOT ATTACHED TO IT.
AH-HA! LOOK AT THAT ONE.
IT'S A PRETTY ONE.
SO MANY TOYS.
"YAHTZEE."
SO NOW WE MAKE
THE PIE DOUGH.
SO 6 POUNDS OF FLOUR?
YEP.
SOME SALT, SOME SHORTENING,
AND SOME COLD WATER.
YES.
FOUND YOUR RECIPE CARD.
YOU HAVE TO REALLY WORK
WITH THE SHORTENING.
THERE I GO.
ALL THE WATER
HOW LONG YOU BEEN MAKIN'
THE PIES HERE?
15 YEARS, 50 PER DAY.
50 PIES A DAY.
YES.
15 YEARS,
5 DAYS IN A WEEK.
YOU'VE MADE 195,000 PIES?
YEP.
THAT'S CRAZY.
OH, THAT'S LOOKIN' GOOD.
HERE WE GO.
KNOCK ALL THE CRUST OFF.
MY APPLES ARE READY.
3/4 OF A CUP
OF SUGAR.
WHAT ELSE IS IN THERE?
HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF CINNAMON.
IS THERE NUTMEG
IN THERE?
LITTLE SALT?
YES, I THINK.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
HOW LONG DOES THAT BAKE?
55 MINUTES AT 350.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE SOME WITH ME?
(Tricia) ABSOLUTELY.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD PIE.
THAT IS SOME FLAKY CRUST.
FRESH APPLES.
THIS IS WONDERFUL PIE.
JUST LIKE HOMEMADE
APPLE PIE.
YOU EVER HAD
A PIE-EATING CONTEST?
I WON ONCE.
REALLY?
SHOULD WE DO ANOTHER ONE
RIGHT NOW?
I'D BEAT HER.
YOU'D BEAT HER IN
A PIE-EATING CONTEST?
OH, IT IS ON.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
TRISH THE OWNER
AGAINST HER CHALLENGER,
THE WIZARD OF THE MIDWEST!
LISA... LISA!
GO!
WOW, SHE'S TAKIN'
BIG BITES OVER HERE.
WHAT HAPP--OH, TOOK
THE ICE CREAM DOWN.
I'M FEELING TEETH
HITTING THE COUNTER
THROUGH THE PIE PAN.
LISA'S LAUGHIN',
AND TRISH IS ALL BUSINESS.
THIS IS VICIOUS!
(cheering)
EVERYBODY'S A WINNER
AT BOBO'S.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SIGN THAT RIGHT THERE.
COULD SEE THAT HANGIN'
FROM THE CAR.
YOU'RE WATCHING
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."