HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
HEY, GUYS,
YOU READY?
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
COMFORT FOOD...
I FEEL LIKE
I'M EATIN' AT HOME.
SOMETHIN' LOADED
WITH BUTTER AND CHEESE.
I BET YOU THE DEFINITION
OF COMFORT FOOD
HAS A PICTURE
OF THAT ON IT.
BIG BREAKFAST
IN BALTIMORE...
(woman) YOU CAN COME HERE IN
YOUR PAJAMAS, I'M PRETTY SURE,
AND THEY WOULDN'T CARE.
WHERE THEY'RE COATIN'
FRENCH TOAST
WITH CAP'N CRUNCH.
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
THIS IS A NEW TWIST TO SOMETHING
THAT'S COZY AND FAMILIAR.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
(man) GREAT
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
A THIRD-GENERATION JOINT...
MY MOM AND MY GRANDMA
AND MY GREAT-GRANDMA,
WE ALWAYS CAME HERE.
ENJOY.
DOIN' COMFORT FOOD
TEXAS STYLE.
(Guy) YEAH, SUPER TENDER.
JUICY!
WOW.
IN SOUTH FLORIDA...
(Guy) PANCAKES IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY?
PANCAKES ANY TIME
OF THE DAY.
AND WHAT USED
TO BE JUST A BAKERY
WHERE THEY'RE DOIN'
A LOT MORE THAN DESSERT.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH.
I DON'T HAVE
TO DO IT AT HOME.
ORDER UP, PLEASE.
AND A LITTLE PLACE
IN WEST VIRGINIA...
ENJOY YOUR DINNER.
WHERE EVERYBODY FEELS AT HOME.
JUST LIKE MOTHER MADE.
IF THAT'S NOT COMFORT FOOD,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
COMFORT FOOD
IS A GOOD BREAKFAST--
YOU KNOW, EGGS,
PANCAKES, FRENCH TOAST.
WELL, HERE IN BALTIMORE,
THERE'S A PLACE CALLED
THE BLUE MOON CAFE.
NOW THEY'RE DOIN' ALL THOSE,
BUT THEY'RE DOIN' 'EM
KIND OF THEIR OWN WAY.
OKAY, LADIES,
I HAVE CAP'N CRUNCH-
ENCRUSTED FRENCH TOAST.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME I'VE HAD
CEREAL-ENCRUSTED FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU HEARD RIGHT...
THROW IT ALL IN THERE.
COME ON, NOW.
SHARE.
FRENCH TOAST
AND CAP'N CRUNCH.
REAL NICE. YAY!
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
SMOKED SALMON.
THEN THERE'S THIS TAKE
ON A CLASSIC.
(woman) IT'S LIKE
LOX AND BAGELS,
ONLY BETTER THAN BAGELS.
'CAUSE IT'S ON
HOMEMADE CREPES.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S PERFECT.
IT'S LIKE BUTTAH.
REAL HOME COOKING
DISH AFTER DISH.
KEEP YOUR HANDS AND FEET
INSIDE THE RIDE AT ALL TIMES.
ENJOY.
THANK YOU.
(woman) WHETHER IT'S EGGS,
OMELETS, FRENCH TOAST--
ANYBODY CAN FIND SOMETHING
THAT MAKES THEM THINK
OF COMFORT FOOD.
THIS COULD BE CALLED
THE COMFORT BLUE MOON CAFE.
WHO HAD THE HUEVOS
RANCHEROS?
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE IN SOMEBODY'S
HOUSE, AND THEY JUST, LIKE,
MADE YOU WHATEVER YOU WANTED.
NOT JUST SOMEBODY'S HOUSE.
HEY, GUYS.
OWNER AND CHEF SARAH SIMINGTON
LIVES UPSTAIRS.
THERE ISN'T A LOT
OF GETAWAY TIME,
BUT I LIKE BEING HERE SO I'M
ON TOP OF THINGS, LITERALLY.
YO, I NEED
MY BUTTER PLEASE.
NOT ON MY FINGERS.
I WAS RAISED
IN A RESTAURANT.
MY MOM HAD ONE
WHEN I WAS A CHILD,
SO I CAME UP WITH THIS.
AND ALMOST 12 YEARS AGO,
HER MOM FOUND
THIS JOINT FOR RENT.
AN OPPORTUNITY LIKE THIS COMES
AROUND ONCE IN A BLUE MOON.
HOOK IT UP.
EVERYTHING IS JUST
MADE IN MY HEAD,
AND THEN I JUST
PLAY IT OUT.
I NEED CAP'N CRUNCH
CRUSHED UP, PLEASE.
WE'RE MAKIN'
FRENCH TOAST BATTER.
IS THIS LEGIT?
YOU CRUNCHED UP
THE CAP'N?
SURE ENOUGH.
OKAY, SO GIVE ME
THE RUN DOWN.
ALL RIGHT.
AND DO IT QUICKLY,
'CAUSE I MIGHT EAT ALL THAT.
ALL RIGHT, COOL.
YOU GOTTA CRACK
YOUR EGG.
HEAVY CREAM.
SOME VANILLA.
SUGAR.
(whistles)
RIGHT INTO THE BATTER.
AND THEN SOME CINNAMON.
WE'RE NOT EVEN
GONNA NEED TO HAVE
THE CAP'N I-ALMOST-
ATE-IT-ALL CRUNCH.
IT'S GOTTA BE SWEET.
YOU WANT TO DUMP
THE CAP'N CRUNCH IN?
SOME FOR THE BOWL,
SOME FOR ME.
THROW IT ALL IN THERE.
COME ON, NOW.
SHARE.
THIS IS ACTUALLY
AGAINST THE LAW
IF YOU'RE IN
THE CAP'N CRUNCH CLUB.
OKAY, NOW SHAKE IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
HOW WAS THAT?
WHOO-HOO!
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON THE GRILL.
PUT DOWN YOUR BUTTER.
DO YOU WANT TO DO IT?
NO, I'M JUST
GONNA HOLD IT.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU BE THE HOLDER.
AND THEN YOU WANT
TO COAT IT REALLY NICE
SO IT GETS GOOD
AND CRISP.
FLIP IT.
NOW ARE WE--
WHOA.
PAT IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
SO WE GET SOME EXTRA--
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
DOES THE CRUNCH
STAY CRUNCHY?
STAYS CRUNCHY.
AND IT KIND OF
CARAMELIZES THE SUGAR
SO IT GETS THIS REALLY
NICE FLAVOR TO IT.
OKAY.
PUT IT RIGHT ON TOP
OF EACH OTHER--PRESENTATION.
WE'RE GONNA DOLLOP IT WITH
SOME HOMEMADE WHIPPED CREAM.
BLUEBERRIES
AND CAP'N CRUNCH.
SAME TIME?
♪ TA-DA ♪
LOOK AT THAT.
DIG IN.
MMM.
YOU GET THAT NICE,
LITTLE REMEMBRANCE FLAVOR
OF THE CRUNCH.
AND IT'S NOT TOO SWEET.
MNH-MNH. NO,
IT'S REALLY NOT.
MM-HMM,
THE BERRIES--
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU
HAVE FRESH BERRIES--
THE ACIDITY BALANCES
IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
THE HOMEMADE WHIPPED
CREAM IS THE WINNER
RIGHT ON TOP OF IT.
LIKE THE MILK.
WANT A BITE?
(boy) IT'S ESPECIALLY GOOD,
'CAUSE, UH,
CAP'N CRUNCH AND THE OUTSIDE
ARE A LITTLE CRUNCHY,
BUT THE INSIDE OF THE FRENCH
TOAST IS NICE AND SOFT AND WARM.
AND THIS IS
KIND OF NEW TWIST
TO SOMETHING THAT'S
COZY AND FAMILIAR.
IN A PLACE THAT'S BOTH.
YOU GUYS
READY FOR THIS?
THIS IS COMFORT.
I AM SERVING PEOPLE IN MY HOME.
THIS IS MY DINING ROOM.
AND THAT'S REALLY YOUR FEELING
AND YOUR EXPECTATION HERE.
ABSOLUTELY.
THIS IS NOW MY FAVORITE
BREAKFAST PLACE IN BALTIMORE.
IT'S COZY. I FEEL LIKE
I'M EATING AT HOME.
YOU CAN COME HERE IN YOUR
PAJAMAS, I'M PRETTY SURE,
AND THEY WOULDN'T CARE.
THEY JUST WANT YOU
TO LOVE THE FOOD...
ALL RIGHT, LADIES.
FOR BASICS
LIKE BISCUITS AND GRAVY,
TO EGGS BENEDICT
TO THOSE SMOKED SALMON CREPES.
MMM, REALLY
DELICIOUS.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
EVEN A HOMEMADE CHILI VERDE
ON HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
MMM. DELICIOUS..
IT'S GOOD,
'CAUSE I'M FROM CALIFORNIA,
AND IT REMINDS ME OF, LIKE,
FOOD YOU GET FROM HOME.
(man) BROWN SUGAR
OATMEAL PANCAKES.
TASTE LIKE MOM MADE 'EM,
YEAH.
WHAT IS THE DEFINITION
OF COMFORT FOOD?
UH, SOMETHING THAT
MAKES YOU FEEL HAPPY
WHEN YOU'RE SAD,
SOMETHING LOADED
WITH BUTTER AND CHEESE.
LIKE THIS BAD BOY--
A SAVORY MEAT ROLL...
IT'S LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN A CINNAMON ROLL
AND A STROMBOLI.
LOADED WITH SAUSAGE,
CHEESE
AND HOMEMADE PESTO.
OLIVE OIL.
I LIKE CASHEWS
INSTEAD OF PINE NUTS.
SOME GARLIC, AND THEN YOU
THROW IN YOUR FRESH BASIL.
SOME PARMESAN CHEESE--
ORGANIC.
SOME SALT, FRESH-SQUEEZED
LEMON JUICE...
MM-HMM,
I'M FEELIN' IT.
AND THEN A LITTLE
MORE OLIVE OIL...
ON TOP?
TO TRY AND GET IT
TO GO TOGETHER.
OH, WAIT, WE GOTTA
MASH IT DOWN REAL QUICK.
READY?
LOOK AT THE COLOR
ON THAT.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
ROLL IT OUT.
AND IT'S HEADIN'
FOR A HOMEMADE BISCUIT DOUGH.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
COMFORT FOOD.
AND THE PESTO.
ARE YOU REALLY SERIOUS?
OH, YEAH.
AND YOU'RE GONNA
PUT DOWN YOUR SAUSAGE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA SPRINKLE IT
WITH MOZZARELLA CHEESE.
AND THIS IS WORKING
AS SOME OF YOUR BINDER?
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA
ROLL IT UP.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOUR SIDE.
SLICE IT UP, PAT 'EM
DOWN A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEY GO IN FOR
ABOUT A HALF AN HOUR.
OH-HO. WE'RE GONNA
SERVE WHAT ON 'EM?
WE'RE GONNA SAUTE PEPPERS,
MUSHROOMS, ONIONS, TOMATOES.
IT COMES WITH HASH BROWNS
AND A LITTLE FRESH FRUIT.
WOW!
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
ROCK ON.
SEE HOW IT JUST
FLAKES APART WITH THE...
AND THE PESTO?
MMM.
OH!
IF YOU LOOK
IN THE DICTIONARY,
I BET YOU THE DEFINITION
OF COMFORT FOOD
HAS A PICTURE
OF THAT ON IT.
ALL RIGHT.
SERIOUSLY, TAKE IT AWAY
FROM ME. THAT'S GREAT!
(Guy) IT'S A LOT OF FOOD.
I THINK IT'LL HOLD ME OVER
FOR THE ENTIRE DAY.
THE BEST BREAKFAST
IN BALTIMORE.
(man) IF YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE BREAKFAST
IN ONE PLACE IN BALTIMORE,
YOU GOTTA COME HERE.
(Guy) FOR 12 YEARS
YOU'VE BEEN DOIN' THIS.
(Sarah) YES.
THAT'S REMARKABLE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE DOIN'
SO WELL, ISN'T IT?
IT IS INDEED.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
GREAT COOKIN'
WITH YA.
POW.
UP NEXT...
GIVE ME A HOT PORK.
WE'RE HEADIN' FOR SAN ANTONIO
WHERE ONE FAMILY'S
BEEN DISHIN' OUT
COMFORT FOOD...
(Guy) THAT IS
OUTRAGEOUS.
FOR THREE GENERATIONS.
FROM THE SEATS TO THE FOOD
TO THE PEOPLE
TO THE--
EVERYTHING'S
THE SAME.
YOU KNOW, COMFORT FOOD
MAY SOUND SIMPLE,
BUT THERE'S A REAL ART
TO GETTING IT RIGHT,
AND TO KEEPING IT THAT WAY,
WHICH IS WHAT 3 GENERATIONS
HAVE BEEN DOIN' FOR 70 YEARS
HERE IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
AT THE TIP TOP CAFE.
(man) GIVE ME A HOT PORK.
MORE ONION RINGS.
THANK YOU.
GRAVY AND MASHED POTATOES.
THREE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAKS.
I LOVE THE CHICKEN-
FRIED STEAK.
THE FOOD'S AMAZING.
HEY, GUYS.
ENCHILADAS.
BEEN COMIN' HERE
FOR 50 YEARS.
40 YEARS.
WELL, HELLO THERE!
MY MOM AND MY GRANDMA
AND MY GREAT-GRANDMA,
WE ALWAYS CAME HERE.
IT'S JUST BASIC
HOME COOKING.
(Guy) YEAH.
IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN GREAT.
EVER SINCE PAPPY DE WESE
OPENED THE JOINT
BACK IN '38...
ENJOY.
THEN PASSED IT ON
TO HIS SON ANSEL.
WELL, MY DAD RETIRED
IN '81.
NOW IT'S IN HIS DAUGHTER
LINDA'S HANDS.
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
I KNOW IT'S A BUSINESS, BUT
IT'S MORE FAMILY THAN ANYTHING.
PAUL, YOU'LL BE NEXT.
AND THE FOOD
IS FABULOUS.
EVERYTHING'S PREPARED
ACCORDING TO OLD RECIPES,
WITHOUT A DOUBT.
(Guy) FROM THE SEATS
TO THE FOOD
TO THE PEOPLE
TO THE--
EVERYTHING'S
THE SAME.
WE JUST LIKE DOIN' IT THE WAY
WE DO IT AND HAVE FOR 70 YEARS.
ENJOY.
SERVIN' UP
COMFORT FOOD, PLUS...
PORK SHORT RIBS.
THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
(man) CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS,
CORN CASSEROLE
AND MASHED POTATOES.
IT'S, UH, OUTSTANDING.
(man) CHICKEN-FRIED
STEAK.
THIS IS THE BEST
AROUND.
GIVE ME
A HOT PORK.
(woman) THE PORK
IS VERY TENDER.
THE GRAVY IS REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
SO WHAT ARE
WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A MARINADE
FOR OUR ROAST PORK.
BROWN SUGAR.
CELERY SALT.
MUSTARD.
GARLIC POWDER.
THERE YOU GO.
SAME TEAM.
GINGER.
MARY ANN.
SO YOU GOTTA
MIX THAT ALL TOGETHER.
LITTLE BIT.
CIDER VINEGAR.
GOTTA ADD A LITTLE ACID
TO BREAK THAT DOWN.
LIQUID SMOKE.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
SOY SAUCE.
HOLY OIL, BATMAN!
THIS IS OIL COUNTRY,
AIN'T IT?
YES, IT IS.
NOW WE JUST PUT IT
ON THE ROAST PORK.
SO THAT'S A PORK SHOULDER
OR BOSTON BUTT,
WHATEVER YOU MIGHT
WANT TO CALL IT.
OH-HO, THAT'S GRAVY GOODNESS
RIGHT THERE, TROY.
NOTHIN' WRONG WITH THIS.
SO WHAT'S THE LAST STEP?
BLACK PEPPER
AND ROSEMARY.
(moans)
NOW HOW LONG YOU GONNA
LET THAT MARINATE?
OVERNIGHT.
NOW IT'S READY TO GO DOWN?
3 1/2, 4 HOURS--
350 DEGREES.
I'LL STAY HERE
AND GUARD IT.
YEAH, LOOK AT THE BONES
STARTIN' TO POP OUT.
YOU SEE ALL THAT FAT
SITTIN' IN THERE?
OH, LOOK AT THAT
LITTLE GEM.
THAT IS OUTRAGEOUS.
SUPER TENDER.
WOW!
LET'S MAKE GRAVY.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU MAKE IT,
AND I'LL WATCH.
ALL RIGHT.
TO GET THE BROWN GRAVY,
PUT SOME WATER IN HERE.
DEGLAZE THE BOTTOM OF IT.
LOOSEN THAT UP.
STRAIN IT INTO OUR POT,
BRING IT TO A BOIL,
AND THEN THICKEN IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF ROUX.
RIGHT.
BOY, THAT'S TIGHT
AND RICH AND DARK.
GOOD!
PUT IT ON TOAST,
COVER IT WITH
BROWN GRAVY,
SERVE IT WITH MASHED
POTATOES AND A SALAD.
WOW.
THAT PUTS THE SHAMA-LAMA
IN DING-DONG.
(laughs)
I MEAN, LOOK AT IT.
IT JUST FALLS OFF THE BONE.
AWESOME.
ASK ME IN A YEAR
IF THAT'S WHAT WE MAKE
AT MY HOUSE
FOR CHRISTMAS.
SERIOUSLY,
I GOTTA STOP.
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
JUST LIKE IT USED
TO BE 30 YEARS AGO.
'CAUSE ALMOST
NOTHING'S CHANGED.
IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT
FOR YOU TODAY?
THEY'RE STILL CUTTIN'
THEIR OWN STEAKS
AND GRINDIN' THEIR OWN
BEEF FOR BURGERS
AND THE HOMEMADE CHILI
ON THEIR ENCHILADAS.
ENCHILADAS--IS THAT
CONSIDERED A COMFORT FOOD?
YES, SIR.
HOW MANY POUNDS
WE GOT IN HERE?
15.
WE'RE ADDIN'
CHOPPED ONION.
AND YOU WANT ME
TO KIND OF
GET UNDERNEATH THIS
A LITTLE BIT?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
SALT.
YOU HOLD ONTO IT.
BLACK PEPPER.
BEEF BASE.
NOW HOW LONG HAS THIS
RECIPE BEEN MADE?
PROBABLY 50 YEARS
OR MORE.
REALLY.
SOME COMINO HERE.
SOME CUMIN?
CUMIN, YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT THEY CALL IT
IN SOUTH TEXAS.
GARLIC--GARLIC POWDER.
AND THE RAMEKIN?
YEAH.
THAT'S A LOT
TO HOLD ONTO.
(Austrian accent)
YOU CAN FEEL THE POWER
OF THE FOREARM
WHEN I'M WORKING THIS.
(normal voice) SO THIS
IS ALL GONNA COOK DOWN.
PROBABLY A COUPLE HOURS,
JUST COOKIN' LOW.
THIS IS THE MEAT
FOR THE ENCHILADAS.
WE ALSO SERVE A BOWL
OF CHILI OR FRITO PIE.
SAME MEAT.
RIGHT. CHILI POWDER
AND TOMATO SAUCE.
LOOK AT THAT!
OH!
OKAY, SO NOW WHAT
DO WE DO WITH IT?
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER IN IT
AND JUST LET IT SIMMER
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA
TIGHTEN THIS UP
WITH SOME FLOUR
AND COLD WATER.
RIGHT.
AND THEN WE'LL MAKE
ENCHILADAS?
THEN WE'LL MAKE
ENCHILADAS.
TWO RED CORN TORTILLAS.
DROP 'EM IN HOT OIL,
JUST--
TO SOFTEN 'EM UP?
JUST TO SOFTEN 'EM.
A LITTLE PLIABLE?
MONTEREY JACK CHEESE.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
LITTLE BIT OF CHILI.
YELLOW CHEESE.
I WOULDN'T
WALK IN HERE
AND THINK THAT I'M GONNA GET
AN ENCHILADA LIKE THAT.
THAT'S A FANTASTIC
TORTILLA--
NICE AND CREAMY,
ONIONS, CHEESE.
WOW, THAT'S LIKE
GRANDMA'S BLANKET
NEXT TO A FIRE COMFORT.
(laughs)
EXCELLENT.
VERY GOOD.
YOU CAN TELL
IT'S HOMEMADE.
MOST EVERYTHING IS.
TWO ORDERS
ONION RINGS.
THANK YOU.
HOW MANY ONION RINGS
YOU MAKE IN A DAY?
250 POUNDS
WORTH OF 'EM.
OF ONIONS?
YEAH.
THIS GOES ON LIKE THIS
ALL THE TIME?
(Troy) FROM 11:00
TO CLOSIN' TIME.
THE ONION RINGS
ARE WONDERFUL.
AND THEN WHAT
DO WE GOT HERE?
THAT'S FOR
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAKS.
AND IT'S GOT ITS OWN WASH
AND ITS OWN FLOUR?
IT'S LIKE HE'S
MAKING BREAD.
MOST PEOPLE COME
FOR THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK,
BUT I COME
FOR THE SHRIMP.
I LOVE MY SHRIMP.
SO FIRST THEY WENT FLOUR,
THEN THEY GO THE WASH.
WITH EGGS, SALT,
PEPPER AND MILK.
(Troy) CRACKER CRUMBS.
CRACKER CRUMBS.
CRUSHED CRACKERS,
YEAH.
OKAY.
SEE WHAT HIS DID HERE?
THIS IS SOMETHIN' ABOUT
THE OLD SCHOOL IN DINERS.
THEY WOULD JUST TAKE A MOMENT
AND JUST FAN THAT TAIL OUT,
BECAUSE WHEN THEY SERVE
THAT BAD BOY UP,
THEY WANT TO SHOW
THE PRESENTATION.
THAT'S AWESOME.
DROP 'EM AND POP 'EM?
DROP 'EM AND POP 'EM.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THOSE THINGS!
I ONLY LEMON
ONE AT A TIME,
'CAUSE I DON'T LIKE
TO GET MY BATTER SOGGY.
MMM. NICE, BIG,
SUCCULENT, BUTTERY--
YOU WANT A FRIED
SHRIMP DINNER--
THAT'S THE DEFINITION.
THEY'RE THE BEST
FRIED SHRIMP IN TOWN.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S JUST GROWIN' UP
IN SAN ANTONIO.
THERE'S A LOT
OF LOVE
THAT GOES INTO
EVERYTHING HERE.
SHOWS IN THE FOOD,
I THINK.
IT'S THE NUMBER ONE PLACE
TO EAT IN SAN ANTONIO.
(woman) IT MAKES YOU
FEEL GOOD,
AND YOU'RE DEFINITELY FULL
WHEN YOU LEAVE HERE.
I'M GONNA BE
ASLEEP IN THE CAR
AT THE REST STOP.
"I WAS JUST
AT THE TIP TOP."
AND THEY'RE GONNA SAY,
"OH, YOU HAD
SOME OF THAT PORK ROAST,
DID YA?"--"UH-HUH."
PLEASE, GET ME OUTTA HERE.
MOVE.
SERIOUSLY, MOVE.
I CAN'T.
IT'S LIKE KRYPTONITE.
NEXT, WE'RE HEADIN'
TO SOUTH FLORIDA...
JUST LIKE HOME-COOKED.
HUMUNGOUS FLAVOR.
HAPPY FOOD.
WHERE THEY ARE SERIOUS
ABOUT HOMEMADE PANCAKES.
3 POUNDS
OF MELTED BUTTER.
THE PARTY'S GETTIN'
STARTED, MAN!
ON TRIPLE-D,
WHEN WE VISIT A PLACE,
IT'S GOTTA HAVE
THREE THINGS GOIN'--
THE PEOPLE AND THEIR STORY,
THE FOOD AND THE LOCATION.
TODAY, WE'RE AT GRANDPA'S,
WHERE IT STARTED OUT
AS A BAKERY,
THE COMFORT FOOD IS RIGHTEOUS,
AND, HEY, IT'S IN FLORIDA.
FRESH...
CHOCOLATE AND RASPBERRY.
JUST LIKE HOME COOKIN'.
HUMUNGOUS FLAVOR.
HAPPY FOOD.
THE WAY
TO A MAN'S HEART
IS THROUGH
HIS STOMACH, RIGHT?
I FEEL LIKE
I'M EATIN' AT HOME.
DAVID, YOU ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
(Guy) PANCAKES IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY?
PANCAKES ANY TIME
OF THE DAY.
IF IT'S COMFORT FOOD...
(woman) PORK LOIN,
MASHED POTATOES.
THEY'RE DOIN' IT HERE...
(man) PORK'S UP.
FOR BREAKFAST...
WE STARTED OUT
AS A BAKERY.
GOOD ON DOUGHNUTS
AND EVERYTHING, GUYS?
YEP.
TO BURGERS...
IT'S SO GOOD,
I HATE TO TALK.
NEED TO PUT FOOD
INSIDE OF IT.
AND SERIOUS PLATE-FILLIN'
SPECIALS.
THE LAMB SHANK--
REALLY GOOD.
JUST MELTS IN
YOUR MOUTH.
I REMEMBER WHEN IT WAS JUST
A SMALL, LITTLE BAKERY PLACE
IN THE EARLY '70s.
STARTED BY GRAMPA
HIMSELF.
RONNIE GRAMPA--
NOW GRAMPA'S YOUR LAST NAME?
YES, SIR.
YOUR DAD'S DAD--
DID YOU CALL HIM
"GRANDPA GRAMPA"?
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
26 YEARS AGO,
RONNIE BROUGHT GENERAL MANAGER
TOMMY GRIMES ABOARD.
WE HAVE FRESH
SHADOW CAKES.
TOGETHER THEY EXPANDED
THE PLACE NEAR FORT LAUDERDALE
INTO A FULL-FLEDGED
RESTAURANT.
TRIED TO FOLLOW THE PATTERN
OF THE BAKERY
INTO THE RESTAURANT TO GIVE
PEOPLE THE SAME KIND OF STUFF--
THE SAME FEELING.
YEAH.
(man) ORDER UP.
DO YOU NEED ANYTHING ELSE
AT THIS TIME?
NO, THIS IS GREAT.
(woman) IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH.
I DON'T HAVE
TO DO IT AT HOME.
AND WHO'S DOIN' SCRATCH
PANCAKES AT HOME ANYWAY?
THESE ARE WHAT
MY MOM WOULD MAKE.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
WHOSE RECIPE
WAS THIS?
ME.
PASTRY FLOUR.
A LOT OF ELASTICITY.
EXACTLY.
24 OUNCES OF SUGAR.
OH, FULL STEAM AHEAD,
CAPTAIN, AYE.
I LEARNED THAT
ON THE SHIP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
BUTTERMILK.
WE DON'T WANT
TO ADD ALL THE LIQUID
UNTIL WE GET
THE LUMPS OUT.
CLEAR!
HALFWAY AROUND.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
OH, STOP. THIS IS ONE OF
THE MOST IMPORTANT TOOLS
OF THE TRADE--THE SCRAPER.
LET'S GO THIRD SPEED.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
GO AROUND
ONE MORE TIME.
ON TWO OR THREE?
THREE THIS TIME.
OOPS. FOUR.
NO!
48 EGGS.
1 QUART OF FRESH MILK.
YOU MEET PEOPLE THAT ARE EXCITED
ABOUT THINGS THEY'RE DOING.
TELL ME ABOUT
3 POUNDS OF MELTED BUTTER.
3 POUNDS
OF MELTED BUTTER.
THE PARTY'S GETTIN'
STARTED, MAN!
BAKING POWDER, BAKING SODA,
2 OUNCES OF SALT.
THAT'S A PRETTY ELABORATE
PANCAKE MIX.
IT BETTER BE GOOD.
IT'S GONNA BE.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT.
YOU'RE THE PANCAKE MASTER.
AND NOTHING DOWN
ON THERE, HUH?
NOTHING DOWN.
IT'S GOT BUTTER IN IT.
YOU NEVER PAT 'EM,
AND YOU NEVER--
NO, YOU DON'T
MESS WITH 'EM.
RIGHT.
OH-HO, I'M SORRY,
MARY LOU RETTON.
SOME PEOPLE LIKE
A CHUNK OF BUTTER, YOU KNOW?
A CHUNK OF BUTTER!
A CHUNK OF BUTTAH.
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE LAYERS.
IT'S REALLY LIGHT
BUT TEXTURED.
THAT'S GOOD
PANCAKE, MAN.
GRAMPA'S MAKES THE BEST
PANCAKES IN SOUTH FLORIDA.
FLUFFY AND PERFECT.
THAT WAS A LOT
OF WORK, TOO.
YOU GOTTA GIVE 'EM
SOMETHING GOOD,
OR ELSE THEY WON'T
COME BACK.
OH, THEY'RE COMIN' BACK.
I'M HERE MORNING,
NOON AND NIGHT.
HEY, LUNCH IS READY.
BRISKET?
LUNCH?
IT LOOKS LIKE SUPPER.
WE'VE ALMOST HAD EVERYTHING
OVER THE YEARS.
THE SOUPS ARE EXCELLENT.
THEY MAKE FRESH SOUPS EVERY DAY.
IT'S ALL, UH, HOMEMADE.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING
FRESHER THAN HERE.
THE ROLLS ARE DELICIOUS.
RIGHT NOW, I'M
CUTTIN' THE DOUGH.
THIS IS THE ROUNDING PART.
WHAT YEAR IS
THIS THING FROM?
WE BOUGHT THAT
IN 1959.
IF WE WANT TO GIVE THEM
SOMETHING GOOD,
WE DON'T BUY IT.
WE MAKE IT.
IT'S FROM SCRATCH EVERY DAY.
EVERY DAY.
HOMEMADE EVERY DAY.
I LIKE IT.
THAT'S BEGGIN' FOR SOME
GRAVY TO BE SOPPED UP.
AND THAT IS THE PLAN HERE
WITH BIG PLATES
LIKE ROAST PORK
AND STUFFING...
PERFECT--CAN'T HAVE
ONE WITHOUT THE OTHER.
MEATLOAF AND GRAVY...
THAT LOOKS
PRETTY GOOD.
AND ONE OF THEIR
MOST POPULAR SPECIALS...
LAMB SHANK.
I'VE GOTTEN LAMB
SHANK BEFORE,
BUT NEVER QUITE
AS GOOD AS THIS.
(Guy) NOT THAT GOOD.
SO LAMB SHANKS.
PEOPLE ARE LOOKIN'
FOR SOMETHING DIFFERENT
THAT THEY DON'T
MAKE AT HOME.
ADD A LITTLE SALT, A LITTLE
PEPPER. GOT HIGH-GLUTEN FLOUR.
DUST 'EM AND FRY 'EM?
RIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT A VEGETABLE-
OLIVE OIL BLEND.
RIGHT.
THAT'S TO HOLD THE FLAVOR,
PUT A LITTLE SEAR ON IT.
LOVE TEXTURE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LOOKIN'
FOR RIGHT THERE, RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
OH, IT SMELLS DYNAMITE.
LOOK AT THE CRUST THAT'S
BEIN' THROWN ON THAT.
IN THE PAN?
YES, SIR.
RAW ONION.
AND CARROTS.
PLUM TOMATOES.
FRESH ROSEMARY.
LOOKS GOOD.
LITTLE BIG OF GARLIC?
YOU MAKE THE BEEF STOCK?
YES, SIR.
YEAH, OF COURSE.
HIDES BEHIND THE BAKERY/
RESTAURANT THING.
AND THIS GOES
IN THE BIG OVEN.
2 1/2 HOURS, 375.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
A LITTLE OF THIS,
IF YOU WANT.
DO A LITTLE OF THIS
AND A LITTLE OF THAT.
THIS IS OUR
LAMB GRAVY.
WHAT I DO IS I MAKE
THE DRIPPINGS FROM HERE,
AND I MAKE THIS GRAVY.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT JUST FALLS
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
SEND ME HOME AND CALL
ME BUFORD. THAT IS MONEY.
FRESH-MADE ROLL.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHY
THIS ROLL IS INVENTED.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S TENDER.
IT'S SUCCULENT.
IT'S GOT TONS OF JUICE,
TONS OF FLAVOR.
THE GRAVY THAT YOU PUT
ALONGSIDE OF IT
IS SO LEGIT.
THAT IS ON POINT, MAN.
MMM! NICE JOB.
THANKS.
THE FLAVORS, THE TASTE
IS PHENOMENAL.
AND YOU GOT THE HOME-BAKED
BREAD.
JUST LIKE
DOWN-HOME COOKING.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO GO.
AND HAS BEEN...
ARE YOU GUYS
HAPPY TODAY?
FOR DECADES.
I GOTTA GET
ONE OF THOSE.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
OH! STOP.
WE DO EAT AT HOME
OCCASIONALLY.
THANKS FOR COMIN' IN.
OH, YEAH, RIGHT HERE.
IT'S COLUMBUS.
HE WANTS THIS BACK
ON THE "SANTA MARIA."
NEXT UP...
ORDER UP, PLEASE.
JUST LIKE MOTHER MADE.
COMFORT FOOD DOWN HOME...
TELL ME THAT'S NOT
A HUNK OF CORNBREAD.
IN WEST VIRGINIA.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE,
AND I DON'T HAVE TO BAKE IT.
SO HERE WE ARE ROLLIN'
THROUGH CENTRAL CITY,
ONE OF THE MOST HISTORICAL PARTS
OF HUNTINGTON, WEST VIRGINIA.
NOW YOU GOT YOUR
HUNDRED-YEAR-OLD BUILDINGS,
YOUR HOUSES WITH
BIG FRONT PORCHES,
SO OF COURSE YOU'D EXPECT
TO FIND A PLACE LIKE THIS,
CENTRAL CITY CAFE,
FOR SOME REAL-DEAL COMFORT FOOD.
ORDER UP, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
YUMMY.
JUST LIKE MOTHER MADE.
BEST IN TOWN.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
IF THAT'S NOT COMFORT FOOD,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IS.
THE REAL THING.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE, AND I
DON'T HAVE TO BAKE IT.
THEY LEAVE THAT UP
TO DAVE LUTHER...
ORDER UP.
THANK YOU ALL.
AND HIS WIFE, SHERRY.
I LEARNED TO COOK
FROM MY MAMA.
AND TOOK WHAT HIS
MAMA TAUGHT HIM
TO WORK ON THE RAILROAD.
ON THE RAILROAD,
YOU RAN THE FEED CAR.
11 MEALS A WEEK
FOR 85 MEN.
THAT'S CRAZY.
AFTER 17 YEARS
WITH THE RAILROAD,
(Guy) LOOK AT THAT!
HE'S COOKING
FOR THE HOMETOWN CROWD...
IT'S JUST LIKE
EATIN' AT HOME.
ALONGSIDE SHERRY
AND DAUGHTER NIKKI...
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
WHO MOVED BACK
FROM CALIFORNIA
TO HELP BUILD
THE FAMILY BUSINESS.
BETSY.
THANK YOU.
WE STARTED OUT
PRETTY SIMPLE--
BEANS AND CORNBREADS
AND JUST TOOK OFF FROM THERE.
HOW'S THAT, UH,
MEATLOAF?
VERY GOOD.
OH, THE VEGETABLE SOUP'S
THE BEST.
WHITE BEAN CHILI?
OH, YES. THIS IS ONE
OF THE SPECIALTIES HERE.
WHY DO YOU START
WITH THE DRY BEANS?
IT'S FRESH.
YOU START FROM SCRATCH.
YOU'RE GONNA COVER
YOUR BEANS WITH WATER,
AND WE'RE GONNA SIMMER THOSE
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
CHICKEN BREAST.
ABOUT FIVE STALKS OF CELERY.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL?
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
ONE ONION.
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER.
THAT'S CORRECT.
CHICKEN AND SAGE--
BEST FRIENDS.
YES.
WHOO! A LITTLE CLOVE.
PICKLED JALAPEÑOS.
CHICKEN STOCK BASE.
YES, SIR.
CAYENNE.
A LITTLE CUMIN.
JUST A LITTLE SALT.
PEPPER--HOW MUCH?
WHATEVER FEELS
GOOD TO YOU.
THIS IS A CROSS
BETWEEN A CHILI
AND LIKE
A BEAN SOUP.
EXACTLY.
MMM. THAT IS NICE.
CLOVES. MMM.
THAT'S THE SECRET.
THAT'LL MAKE
YOU HAPPY.
ORDER UP.
ESPECIALLY WITH A MONSTER
HELPING OF CORNBREAD.
THIS IS THE BEST YOU
COULD BUY ANYWHERE.
1 CUP OF SUGAR TO HOW MANY
CUPS OF FLOUR? ABOUT 8?
NOW I'VE GOT 10 CUPS
OF CORNMEAL AND FLOUR.
GOT 1 CUP OF OIL.
THEN YOU PUT IN ABOUT 5 EGGS.
BUTTERMILK.
I LIKE THE SIZE
BOWL YOU GOT, BRO.
(chuckles)
WE'LL GET IT ALL
MIXED UP HERE.
LOOK AT ALL
THAT CREAMY GOODNESS.
OH, YEAH.
A WHOLE LOT OF LOVE
COMES OUT
OF THAT CORNBREAD.
IT SMELLS LIKE SWEET
CORN COMIN' OUT OF IT.
MM-HMM.
MMM, WOW, THERE'S SOME
TEXTURE IN THAT,
A LITTLE BIT SWEET.
(Sherry) THEY LIKE A LITTLE
OF THE SWEET IN THIS AREA.
THAT'S HOW YOU GET IT GOIN'
RIGHT THERE.
EXACTLY.
MMM.
ALMOST AS GOOD AS MY
GRANDMOTHER'S CORNBREAD.
WE WANTED PEOPLE TO FEEL
THEY WERE GOING
TO MOM'S HOUSE
FOR DINNER.
BYE, GUYS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THEY'VE JUST MADE ME
FEEL LIKE FAMILY.
AND THE FOOD'S
COMFORT FOOD,
AS ARE THE PEOPLE.
THEY'RE COMFORTABLE.
YOU JUST FEEL WELCOME THE MINUTE
YOU WALK THROUGH THE DOOR.
PEOPLE DO ASK
FOR MOM AND POPS.
MOM, POPS AND DAUGHTERS.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
I'M SORRY, I JUST CAN'T
GET OFF THE CHILI.
(Sherry) PLEASE
CONTINUE.
I MEAN,
CAN YOU GUYS
JUST TALK AMONGST
YOURSELVES FOR A LITTLE BIT?
YES.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
FLORIDA--DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND GATORS.
DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND LEMURS?
ANY RESEMBLANCE?
HERE IN FLORIDA,
HANGIN' OUT WITH SOME FOXES.