HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
COME...
GET IT!
SOMETHIN' DIFFERENT.
IT WAS
THE CARAMELIZED GARLIC.
HERE'S YOUR GRUB.
THE HOTDOG STAND IN
A COUPLE OF SCHOOL BUSES
IN WEST VIRGINIA,
WHERE THEY'RE PILIN',
DEEP FRYIN', AND YOU CAN
EVEN GET 'EM BY THE POUND.
I DIDN'T THINK
IT'D BE THIS BIG.
OH, YEAH,
THEY'VE GOT BURGERS, TOO.
IS THERE ANY ON MY FACE?
OVER TO RICHMOND, VIRGINIA...
JUST OFF THE CHART.
WHATEVER KIND OF FOOD
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
FOR A LOCAL CAFE
WITH A SERIOUS CHEF.
FRESH BASIL.
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF WINE IN THERE.
CAN'T YOU
HEAR IT SINGING?
AND A BAR IN MIAMI
WHERE THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
SOMETHING DIFFERENT
TO GO WITH YOUR BREW.
YOU'RE HAVING
THE ESCARGOT?
PEOPLE WOULD CALL IT
A SPORTS BAR,
AND YOU'RE SERVIN'
ESCARGOT.
IT'S FABULOUS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
SO I'M ROLLIN' THROUGH THE STATE
WHERE MY FATHER WAS BORN,
WEST VIRGINIA,
AND THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT,
BECAUSE IT MIGHT SHED SOME LIGHT
ON WHERE HE LEARNED HOW TO COOK.
AND WHAT BETTER PLACE
TO START THAN THIS JOINT,
HILLBILLY HOT DOGS?
COME...
GET IT.
WE ALL LOVE IT.
WELL, I'VE NEVER SEEN
NOTHIN' LIKE THIS.
SAY GOOD-BYE.
WHAT YOU WANT TO EAT TODAY?
WHEN SONNY KNIGHT
BROUGHT HIS
CALIFORNIA-BORN WIFE SHARIE
HOME TO WEST VIRGINIA...
I'M A CALI-GIRL!
THE SELF-PROCLAIMED
HILLBILLY...
HERE'S YOUR GRUB.
AND HIS WEST COAST BRIDE...
I BROUGHT THE BEVERLY
TO THE HILLBILLIES.
DECIDED TO OPEN THE ULTIMATE
WEST VIRGINIA HOT DOG STAND.
TWO SCHOOL BUSES STACKED UP
NEXT TO A SHED.
(playing harmonica)
YEE-HAW!
AND EVERY YARD SALE ITEM
IN THE WORLD OUT THERE.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
HILLBILLIES ACTUALLY
MAKIN' FUN OF THEMSELVES.
AND MAKIN' SOME SERIOUS DOGS
LOADED WITH EVERY COMBINATION
OF JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
(speaking indistinctly)
PIZZA DOGS.
THE EGG DOG.
I'M MAKIN' A TACO DOG
RIGHT NOW.
YOU GONNA COME EAT IT?
HOW'S YOUR DOG?
OH, IT'S GREAT.
EVEN DEEP-FRIED.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
AND UP TO A FULL POUND.
I DIDN'T THINK
IT'D BE THIS BIG.
AND AT HE HEART
OF THE MENU
HERE YOU GO.
A GROUND BEEF SAUCE
FOR THE DOGS.
(man) THIS IS THE CLOSEST
TO THE SAUCE
THAT THEY SERVED US
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
(man) IT SOUNDS
KIND OF BIZARRE,
BUT IT HAS
A COMPLEXITY TO IT.
(laughs)
IT REALLY DOES.
IT STARTED
WITH HIS MOTHER'S RECIPE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE...
THE MEAT.
OKAY, HERE'S--
WHERE DID WE GET LOST?
WE ONLY GOT THE TUB OUT.
AND THEN WE GOT STUCK
AT "MEAT."
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE WATER.
WE'RE GONNA POUR IT IN THERE.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO
IS WE WANT TO MIX IT UP
SO THAT WE KIND OF GET IT
SO IT'S REAL FINE.
GET SOME GLOVES ON YOU.
GLOVES? I NEED, LIKE,
HIP WADERS.
DOES PAUL BUNYAN
WORK HERE?
THROW IN SOME RED PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER, SALT
ONION POWDER, GARLIC,
CHILI POWDER,
AND TOMATO PASTE.
SHE'S ALL YOURS.
WHAT ABOUT THOSE UNCONVENTIONAL
TOOLS CALLED SPOONS?
OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO, NO, NO.
WHY DIRTY ONE?
THAT'S MORE DISHES TO DO
AT THE END OF THE NIGHT.
"WHY--"
"WHY DIRTY ONE?"
THIS IS LOOKIN'
WONDERFUL!
IT'S KIND OF
LIKE MEAT PUDDING.
YOU'RE DOIN' A GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU.
THAT LOOKS PERFECT.
YEE-HAW!
IT'S READY TO GO
ON THE BURNER.
SO WE'RE GONNA COME
OVER HERE AND GRAB A WEENIE,
COUPLE JALAPEÑOS,
NACHO CHEESE,
BARBECUE--
BARBECUE?
MUSTARD.
MAYONNAISE.
KETCHUP.
YOU'RE MAKIN' SOUP.
THEN MY SAUCE.
ONION, COLESLAW,
LITTLE BIT
OF THE RELISH,
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
KRAUT?
OKAY, AND THEN KRAUT.
OKAY.
MMM! I WENT
THROUGH THE LAYERS.
OH, THAT'S TASTY.
WOW, THERE'S SOMETHIN'
SPICY IN THERE.
JALAPEÑO.
A LITTLE JALAPEÑO.
BUT IT'S NOT AS HOT
AS THIS ONE.,
WITH TWO KINDS OF PEPPERS
INVENTED FOR
ONE OF THE REGULARS.
(Sharie)
CONGRESSMAN RAHALL.
THE CONGRESSMAN
COMES HERE--
COMES HERE.
YES, HE DOES.
CONGRESSMAN,
HOW ARE YOU?
YES, SIR, FINE.
HOW'S YOUR DOG?
OH, IT'S GREAT.
NOW THIS IS
NAMED AFTER YOU.
YES, THIS IS
THE RAHALL RED-HOT WEENIE.
AND IT IS HOT.
I SAID, I WANT THIS,
THIS AND THIS
FROM THEIR MENU
OF INGREDIENTS.
I ADDED A FEW OF MY OWN.
IT'S GOT HOT MUSTARD,
SAUERKRAUT, FRIED ONION,
GREEN PEPPERS...
AND OF COURSE HABANERO
AND JALAPEÑOS.
IT'S BREAKIN'
A SWEAT OUT ON ME.
BUT YOU DON'T NEED
TO BE A VIP
TO GET YOUR OWN DOG HERE.
"STACEY'S FLU SHOT"?
HE SAID, "JUST PILE THAT WEENIE
WITH A LOT OF JALAPEÑO."
IT'S ACTUALLY QUITE GOOD.
WHO'S CHUCK?
CHUCK IS ONE
OF OUR CUSTOMERS.
HE CAME IN AND SAID, "I WANT
EVERY CONDIMENT YOU HAVE."
AND THEY CALLED IT CHUCK'S...
...JUNK YARD DOG.
WE NEED ONE THAT'S DEEP-FRIED
WITH THE CHILI SAUCE
WITH THE HABANERO SAUCE.
♪ I GOT A HOME WRECKER ♪
BIG, GOOD HOT DOG.
(Sonny) 15 INCHES LONG.
1-POUND ALL-BEEF WEENIE.
(Sharie laughs)
THROW IT IN
THE DEEP FRYER.
YOU PUT A LITTLE
CRUNCH ON THAT.
START WITH A COUPLE
JALAPEÑOS.
WAY TO WEDGE 'EM RIGHT
DOWN IN THERE AND HIDE 'EM.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE HABANERO SAUCE?
CHOP, CHOP, CHOP, CHOP.
THIS IS GONNA ADD
THE EXTENDED HEAT.
'CAUSE THE 95 JALAPEÑOS
YOU PUT IN--
THOSE AREN'T GONNA HURT.
COLESLAW.
THAT IS WHAT COOLS IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU NEED YOUR ROUGHAGE,
JUST TO GARNISH.
THERE IT IS.
(laughter)
(Sharie) ISN'T THAT
WONDERFUL?
YEAH.
OH, MY GOD, THAT'S HOT!
IT'S SPICY,
BUT IT'S GOOD.
EAT IT IN 12 MINUTES,
AND YOU GET A FREE T-SHIRT.
YOU GET A HOME WRECKER
SHIRT.
I THINK IT'D TAKE ME
ABOUT A WEEK.
YOU'VE EATEN
A HOME WRECKER?
ABSOLUTELY.
9 MINUTES
AND 33 SECONDS.
"I GRUBBED ONE
AND GOT THIS FREE SHIRT."
IS THIS YOUR BROTHER?
THIS IS MY BROTHER.
IT IS YOUR BROTHER!
HOW'D YOU KNOW?
HE'S THE ONE
THAT NAMED IT!
HOME WRECKER.
AND IF THE HOME WRECKER'S
NOT BIG ENOUGH FOR YOU,
THEY'VE GOT A BURGER THE SIZE
OF A MANHOLE COVER--
THE SINGLE WIDE.
JUST HALF OF IT'S BIGGER
THAN MY HEAD.
(Sonny) IT'S ABOUT 3 1/2
POUNDS OF PURE BEEF,
WE GET IT EVERY DAY--
NEVER FROZEN.
WE PUT THIS GOOD
FLAVOR TO IT.
A LITTLE SALT.
A LITTLE PEPPER.
LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
YEP.
OPENS THE PORES.
WE GOT THE BUN.
THAT'S BODACIOUS.
PUT A LITTLE BUTTER ON IT.
PUT IT ON THE FLATTOP.
IT'S A BIG,
ANGRY BURGER.
(Austrian accent) YOU REALLY
GOT TO GET YOUR ARMS INTO IT
AND PRESS IT RIGHT.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHEN YOU'RE GOING
TO MAKE IT OR BREAK IT.
GO AHEAD.
OKAY!
WHEE!
(normal voice) ALL RIGHT,
ACES ARE WILD.
PICK A CHEDDAR.
WHAA!
HONEY, GET AN APPLICATION.
I'VE LEARNED
FROM MY SWEETHEART
THAT IT'S PRESENTATION.
IT IS.
WE EAT WITH OUR EYES.
THAT'S THE BIGGEST BURGER
I'VE EVER MADE.
(imitates unsheathing
sword)
(exhales deeply)
IS THERE ANY ON MY FACE?
IS THERE SOME IN MY EAR?
MMM!
I'M TELLIN' YA,
THIS IS TASTY.
AT THE RATE YOU
WERE GOIN' AT THAT,
YOU COULD HAVE
HAD THIS THING.
I GOTTA BE IN
A 1-PIECE LEOTARD.
I HAVE BALLET ON THURSDAYS.
(man) TASTES GREAT.
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING ON IT.
A REAL GOOD HAMBURGER.
EVERYBODY THAT DOES COME HERE
ENDS UP LOVIN' IT
AND COMIN' BACK.
TO WORK THEIR WAY
THROUGH THE MENU...
PIZZA DOG. TACO DOG.
WEST VIRGINIA DOG.
ENJOY THE DECOR...
MY NAME'S ON HERE SOMEWHERE.
IN A BUS!
HURRY UP!
AND THE HOSPITALITY.
HOW'S THE GRUB?
EVERYTHING OKAY?
(Sharie) YOU WANT
SOME FRIES WITH THAT?
ARE YOU KIDDIN'?
(man) THEY'RE JUST
ABSOLUTE CHARACTERS.
AND THE ATMOSPHERE
IS PRICELESS.
♪ HOME WRECKER ♪
NEXT, WE'RE HEADIN' OVER
TO VIRGINIA...
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
WHERE THE PIZZA'S ARE GREEN...
OH, MAN, THAT'S GOOD.
THE PASTA'S GONE GREEK...
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH FETA
IN PASTA DISHES.
AND JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING
IS SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
LITTLE HOUSE,
BIG FLAVOR.
CHECK OUT THIS JOINT
IN RICHMOND, VIRGINIA,
DOT'S BACK INN.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE,
WELL, A SMALL COMPACT CAR
WITH A BIG SUPER-CHARGED ENGINE
COMIN' OUT OF THE HOOD--
SMALL, LITTLE, NONDESCRIPT JOINT
WITH TONS OF CUSTOM-BUILT FOOD.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S JUST OFF THE CHART.
WHATEVER KIND OF FOOD
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
ALL DONE A LITTLE DIFFERENTLY.
WHEN YOU TASTE IT, YOU'RE
GONNA RECOGNIZE THE DIFFERENCE.
(Guy) CHEESE
AND APPLE OMELET?
I'M HAVING
MEDITERRANEAN PIE.
IT'S LIKE A PIZZA, BUT IT'S
GOT THE GREEK ASPECT TO IT
WITH THIS FETA CHEESE.
(man) I'M EATING
THE BLACK BEAN CORN CAKES.
IT'S AWESOME.
LITTLE HOUSE.
BIG FLAVOR.
ALL WHIPPED UP
BY A CULINARY INSTITUTE GRAD,
JIMMY TSAMOURAS...
PUT A LITTLE
TOMATOES ON TOP.
WHO'D BEEN EATING HERE
FOR 15 YEARS...
JOEY, ORDER UP.
AND FINALLY CONVINCED
OWNER COOKIE GIANNINI
TO SELL HIM THE PLACE
ALMOST A YEAR AND A HALF AGO.
SO YOU HAD THE RESTAURANT
FOR HOW LONG?
16 YEARS.
I STARTED COMIN' BY
MORE AND MORE OFTEN
AND WOOING HER.
IT HAPPENED
VERY QUICKLY.
AND I PROMISED HER I
WASN'T GONNA CHANGE IT.
AND HE KEPT HIS WORD.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
THE BRUNCH IS EXCEPTIONAL.
I GET THE CHICKEN MacARTHUR,
AND THAT'S ALWAYS GOOD ANYTIME.
(Guy) CHICKEN MacARTHUR?
MacARTHUR AVENUE.
MacARTHUR, AVENUE.
WE ARE ON
MacARTHUR AVENUE.
FAIR AMOUNT OF OLIVE OIL, 'CAUSE
THAT'S BASICALLY OUR SAUCE.
WHOA!
LOOK AT THAT, MAN.
YOU REALLY CAN CUT.
I GOT THOSE
ONIONS SO THIN,
THEY ONLY GOT ONE SIDE.
(scoffs)
TO ME THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING IS
IS THAT YOU DON'T
BURN THE GARLIC.
WE WANT TO ADD OUR CHICKEN.
BUT WE DON'T WANT TO LET IT
GET TO THE POINT--
SO YOU PUT THE PROTEIN IN NOW,
CLOSE DOWN THE COOKING PROCESS.
THAT IS CORRECT.
SO IT DOESN'T LET
THAT GARLIC BURN.
YOU WANT TO STIR THAT UP
A LITTLE BIT?
I'M NOT A STIRRER.
I'M A TOSSER.
ALL RIGHT,
WELL, TOSS IT.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
LITTLE, UH, KOSHER SALT?
KOSHER SALT MIXED
WITH WHITE PEPPER.
HOW 'BOUT SOME
ARTICHOKE HEARTS?
OKAY, WE'RE READY FOR IT.
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF WINE IN THERE.
WE THROW IN A LITTLE BIT
OF, UH, SPAGHETTI.
FETA CHEESE, MAN.
WHAT WE DON'T WANT
IS TO BE CREAMY
AND THEN JUST MELT AWAY,
OKAY?
WE WANT TO HAVE SOME
NICE CHUNKS--
SO IT HAS TO HAVE
SOME TEXTURE.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WITH FETA.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
NO.
MORE?
YEAH. LOOK AT THAT SAUCE
THAT'S COMIN' UP RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S MONEY, BABY.
IF YOU TUNE INTO
THIS SHOW AGAIN,
AND HE HAS BLONDE HAIR...
PUT IT DOWN FOR
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES?
YEAH, IT'LL
MELT THE FETA,
HEAT UP THE PASTA
A LITTLE BIT.
I'M GONNA DO YOUR TOSS.
WHOA! HEY!
THROW IN OUR TOMATOES.
WHAT I'VE FOUND IS IF YOU
START STIRRING YOUR PASTA,
EVERYTHING'LL COME
TO THE MIDDLE--
ALL YOUR PASTA WILL
COME TO THE MIDDLE,
AND ALL YOUR GOODY STUFF
WILL GO TO THE OUTSIDE.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
THIS IS THE WAY TO DO IT.
PUT IT ON OUR PLATE.
WE'LL TWIST IT A LITTLE BIT
LIKE THAT, OKAY?
AH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
AND THEN WE'LL TAKE
ALL OUR GOODY STUFF,
AND WE'LL JUST KIND OF
MOUND IT ON TOP.
LITTLE ONION IN THERE--
LITTLE NICE, FRESH SCALLION.
GET SOME PARMESAN.
HOW 'BOUT THAT?
SMELL GOOD?
MAN!
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHAT
I THINK, DON'T YOU?
IT'S LIKE TALKING
IN THE MIDDLE OF AN OPERA.
CAN'T YOU HEAR IT SINGING?
OH, THAT'S GOOD, MAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH FETA
IN PASTA DISHES.
THAT FETA IS
JUST REALLY POPPING.
IT GIVES A NICE, BRINY, SALTY,
VINEGARY TYPE OF--
MMM!
TOMATOES, GOOD PASTA,
SOME FRESH CHICKEN.
IT'S A NICE TASTE.
IT HAS MY FAVORITE--
ARTICHOKES.
AND THE PASTA'S AL DENTE?
YES.
VERY IMPORTANT.
YOU WOULD KNOW.
CAN'T BEAT THIS PLACE.
FOR A WHOLE MENU
FILLED WITH DISHES DONE
JUST A LITTLE DIFFERENT...
I'M HAVING
PIGS IN A BLANKET.
BUT MADE WITH ANDOUILLE
FROM LOUISIANA.
(girl) THE PANCAKE
IS KIND OF SWEET.
THE SAUSAGE
IS KIND OF SPICY.
THERE'S SOMETHING
CALLED THE CHUNKY MONKEY...
BANANA WITH CHOCOLATE CHIPS
WRAPPED IN A PANCAKE.
AND CORN CAKES TOPPED WITH
BLACK BEANS,
MELTED CHEESE,
SOME SOUR CREAM
ONIONS, PEPPERS,
TOMATOES AND SALSA.
THAT'S GOOD.
THOSE BEANS ARE REALLY TASTY.
THE SALSA'S REALLY GOOD.
THAT'S GREAT.
EVEN THEIR TAKE
ON PIZZA'S DIFFERENT--
ON A PITA WITH GREEN SAUCE
INSTEAD OF RED.
THIS IS OUR PESTO FOR OUR
MEDITERRANEAN PIE.
LET'S ADD SOME GARLIC,
FRESH BASIL
AND YOU'RE
USING WALNUTS
AS OPPOSED TO PINE NUTS?
I LIKE THE WALNUTS BETTER.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
OLIVE OIL.
WHOO!
MMM.
AND WE'LL SPREAD IT ON
DELICIOUSLY.
WE'LL TAKE THESE
AND WE'LL SHINGLE 'EM ON.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE NICE,
CRUMBLED FETA CHEESE.
WE'LL THROW THAT ON TOP.
WE TAKE IT, AND WE'RE GONNA
THROW IT IN OUR OVEN,
ALL THE WAY IN THE BACK.
OH, MAN, THAT'S GOOD.
AND THEY'RE DOIN' BURGERS
THEIR WAY--
WITH MELTED BLUE CHEESE
IF YOU WANT,
AND HOMEMADE FRIES,
AND A FAVORITE CALLED
THE SAILOR SANDWICH.
I'VE BEEN EATIN' THIS
FOR 17 YEARS, AND I LOVE IT.
LET'S MAKE THE SAILOR.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S DO IT.
WE THROW OUR KNOCKWURST
ON OUR GRILL.
CAN'T KNOCK THE 'WURST.
THROW OUR PASTRAMI ON.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKIN'
PASTRAMI.
IF I COME BACK, I'M GONNA COME
BACK AS A PASTRAMI SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THAT.
GOLDEN-BROWN.
IT'S A NICE PIECE OF RYE.
IT'S A GREAT PORTION
OF PASTRAMI.
THE KNOCKWURST IS
A NICE TEXTURE DIFFERENCE.
THE SWISS IS MELTED,
AND YOU PUT DIJON ON IT.
I THINK ONE OF THE THINGS
ABOUT BEING A CHEF
IS THE BALANCE--THE RIGHT
INGREDIENTS DONE THE RIGHT WAY.
EXCELLENT.
THAT COULD COMPETE
WITH ANY NEW YORK DELI.
I'M AN EX SAILOR.
THAT'S AN EXCEPTIONAL
SAILOR SANDWICH.
ORDER ANYTHING ON THE MENU,
AND IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
AS GOOD AS ALWAYS...
PIGS IN A BLANKET.
TRUE-BLUE PANCAKES.
I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE
FOR ABOUT 17 YEARS.
AT LEAST TWICE A WEEK.
EVERY SUNDAY MORNING
AT LEAST.
MONSTER RECIPES.
YOU ALWAYS KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT
WHEN YOU WALK IN THE DOOR.
GOOD FOOD. GOOD FRIENDS.
GOOD PLACE TO COME.
ENJOY IT.
YOU GUYS CAN GO TO COMMERCIAL.
I'M GONNA CONTINUE TO EAT THIS.
I'LL SEE YOU IN A MINUTE.
WOW!
COMIN' UP...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
WE'RE AT A BAR IN FLORIDA
WITH THE BAR FOOD BASICS...
TEN WINGS,
BUFFALO STYLE.
LIKE ESCARGOT.
MMM, NOTHIN' LIKE
A LITTLE SNAIL AND CHEESE.
I'M HERE IN MIAMI,
WHERE 20 YEARS AGO,
A FLIGHT ATTENDANT
AND A CARPENTER
TOOK A CHANCE
TO OPEN A RESTAURANT.
NOW, IT DIDN'T LOOK LIKE MUCH.
IT'S HERE IN A STRIP MALL.
BUT THEY HAD A PLAN.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
(Guys) PEOPLE WOULD CALL
IT A SPORTS BAR...
YOU'RE HAVING
THE ESCARGOT?
AND YOU'RE
SERVING ESCARGOT.
YEP.
IT'S FABULOUS.
MUSSELS PROVENCAL,
BLACKENED MAHIMAHI...
IT'S GOT A NICE
KICK TO IT.
CHICKEN FRANCESE...
THE SEARED TUNA.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
TEN WINGS,
BUFFALO STYLE.
EVEN THE BAR FOOD'S
OVER THE TOP.
GOURMET WINGS.
IT'S LIKE CHICKEN PICCATA
ON A STICK.
WHAT YOU DON'T EXPECT,
YOU'LL GET HERE.
(man) I DO THIS FOOD 'CAUSE I
WORKED IN A FRENCH RESTAURANT.
YOU GOT GUYS
IN CHEF COATS.
DUDE, YOU'RE LEGIT.
CHRIS HIRSH STARTED WORKIN' IN
THE RESTAURANT BIZ AT 14...
ROCK 'N' ROLL...
AND GOT OUT AT 26 TO GO
INTO CONSTRUCTION.
A PERSON ORDERING A CAKE...
AND THEN HIS WIFE CASS
WON A KIND OF LOTTERY
THE STATE OF FLORIDA RUNS
TO HAND OUT SOME
LIQUOR LICENSES.
(Cass) SO I SAID,
"LOOK, YOU CAN BUILD BARS.
YOU'RE A CHEF."
HAD EITHER OF YOU MANAGED OR
OWNED RESTAURANTS BEFORE THIS?
NO.
BUT THEY WEREN'T GONNA DO IT
THE STANDARD WAY ANYWAY.
PICK UP...
CHRIS INTRODUCED DIFFERENT
THINGS TO THESE PEOPLE.
AND THEY'VE JUST LEARNED
TO LOVE HIS CUISINE.
WHAT DOES CHRIS DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
BUT IT'S MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH
DELICIOUS.
THE DOLPHIN--
IT WAS ALWAYS VERY GOOD.
ONE ENCRUSTED DOLPHIN.
(Guy) DOLPHIN SANDWICH?
NOT FLIPPER.
MAHIMAHI.
OH, MAHIMAHI.
POTATO-CHIP-ENCRUSTED
MAHIMAHI.
THE END OF EVERY BAG
OF POTATO CHIPS.
NO ONE WANTS THE CRUMBS.
THROWIN' 'EM AWAY!
ONE DAY, I JUST SAID IT.
"I GOTTA DO SOMETHIN'
WITH THIS."
SO FIRST YOU MAKE
YOUR FRANCESE,
WHICH IS THE EGGS--
EGGS. WE'RE GONNA
GIVE IT THE PARSLEY,
PARMESAN, SPRINKLE OF SALT
AND WHITE PEPPER.
YOU WANT A LITTLE WATER
IN THERE, TOO?
WE ADD A LITTLE WATER.
SO FROM THERE, FLOUR,
EGG, OUR POTATO CHIPS
THAT WE BROKE UP
A LITTLE BIT.
LOOK HOW NICE AND FIRM
AND FRESH THAT IS.
REAL NICE PIECE OF MEAT.
WE GET EVERYTHING IN FRESH.
BUTTERFLY IT A LITTLE BIT.
JUST TO MAKE IT SO IT
COOKS A LITTLE FASTER.
WE WANT IT TO LOOK GOOD
ON THE BUNS.
IT'S GONNA OVERLAP THOSE BUNS.
IT'S GONNA LOOK GREAT.
A LITTLE FLOUR,
EGG WASH...
AND THEN YOU PUT IT IN.
OKAY, I LIKE THAT.
SHAKE IT A LITTLE BIT.
VOILA.
AND THAT'S IT.
FLASH FRY ON THE OUTSIDE.
SOME NICE GOLD-BROWN
CHIPS ON THERE.
IT'S VERY NICE.
IT'S LIKE WHEN I'D EAT
A SANDWICH WHEN I WAS A KID.
I USED TO PILE
MY CHIPS ON IT.
RIGHT ON THE BUN
LIKE THAT.
LET'S GET
INTO THE HUNCH.
HA--HOT.
MMM.
UH-HUH.
THE FISH IS SUPER,
SUPER FRESH.
RIGHT.
THE POTATO CHIP--
YOU COAT THAT TO THE FISH--
LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHIN', MAN.
THAT MIGHT BE SOME OF THE BEST
BATTER I'VE EVER HAD ON FISH.
IF SOMEBODY SAYS THEY
WANT A FISH SANDWICH,
THAT SHOULD BE
THE SANDWICH.
VERY GOOD.
ALL THESE THINGS MIXED UP, AND
THEN YOU STILL TASTE THE FISH.
VERY NICE.
AND WHAT ELSE DO YOU
USE THIS, UH, FRANCESE--
WELL, ANYTHING--
FRAHN-CHAZE.
ANYTHING WE BATTER.
WE USE IT FOR OUR
CHICKEN FRANCESE.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
DIG IT.
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
HOME COOKED
FROM SCRATCH.
(woman) PEPPERCORN DRESSING.
(Guy) MAKES IT HIMSELF?
SHOULD BOTT--HE SHOULD
BOTTLE IT, OH, YEAH.
HOMEMADE CROUTONS
FROM LEFTOVER BREAD.
WOW, THOSE ARE
GOOD CROUTONS.
AND LOOK AT ALL THE DIFFERENT
SAUCES BEING HELD.
THAT TARTAR SAUCE
IS LEGIT.
AND THAT SCAMPI BUTTER
WITH SHALLOTS, GARLIC--
I PUT MY JUICES IN, WHICH IS
WHITE WINE AND LEMON JUICE.
MMM, IT'S TASTY ALREADY.
AND THEY USE IT
ALL OVER THE PLACE...
TAKEOUT, ONE MUSSEL.
FROM MUSSELS PROVENCAL
TO OYSTERS WITH JALAPEÑOS,
LEMON JUICE
AND A LITTLE PROVOLONE,
TO ESCARGOT.
YEAH, THIS IS
EXACTLY THE PROCESS
I THOUGHT I'D BE FINDING
WHEN I PULLED UP TO SCULLY'S.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
PASS US BY--
DON'T KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE GONNA MISS.
I LOOKED AT THE MENU.
I SAID,
"OH, THEY HAVE ESCARGOT."
SO YOU FIND THAT AT
EVERY BAR JOINT, RIGHT?
THEY SERVE IT TO YOU
JUST LIKE YOU WOULD GET IT
IN A FRENCH RESTAURANT.
HANDS DOWN, THE FIRST
TIME WE'VE EVER SEEN
ESCARGOT ON A MENU,
BUT IT GOES OVER WELL?
FANTASTIC.
PEOPLE LOVE IT?
THEY LOVE IT.
WELL, LET'S QUIT TALKIN'.
LET'S DO IT, THEN.
LET'S DO IT.
MY PAN'S HOT ALREADY.
SIX MUSHROOMS.
OKAY, IS THIS NEW MATH?
'CAUSE YOU GOT SEVEN.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY.
WE'LL PUT A LITTLE OIL
IN THERE FIRST,
JUST TO GET IT STARTED.
THEN WE TAKE OUR
BELGIUM ESCARGOT.
GOT A LITTLE SEASONING
WITH SALT AND WHITE PEPPER.
AND THEN AS WE MADE EARLIER,
OUR GARLIC BUTTER.
SO EVERYBODY
COMES TO TEMPERATURE
TOGETHER?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUT OUR MUSHROOMS.
TAKE OUR ESCARGOT.
AND THIS IS A BIG
SELLER ON THE MENU?
BIG-TIME.
PEOPLE COME AND HAVE THAT,
A COUPLE APPETIZERS
AND MAKE IT A MEAL.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE PROVOLONE CHEESE.
THROW THAT UP IN
THE, UH, CHEESE MELTER?
YOU GOT IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL.
DUDE, I'VE SEEN
SOME ESCARGOT IN MY DAY.
THAT'S PRETTY
WELL DONE UP.
NOTHIN' LIKE A LITTLE
SNAIL AND CHEESE.
I'VE HAD SO MANY ESCARGOT
WHERE THEY'RE SO CHEWY.
THAT WAS SO DELICATE,
IT WAS LIKE...
IT WAS LIKE BUTTAH.
OH, MAN.
WHAT YOU GETTING AFTER?
A LITTLE ESCARGOT?
IT'S GOOD?
EXCELLENT.
VERY FRESH.
VERY WELL COOKED.
VERY TENDER.
MMM, IT'S SO GOOD.
I ASKED FOR EXTRA GARLIC,
AND YOU GET IT.
I DIDN'T SEE
WHERE IT SAID
"LE SPORTS BAR
ET LE PUB."
AT LEAST I CAN COME
AND LOOK ON THIS MENU.
BESIDES THE ESCARGOT
AND THEN THE DOLPHIN
AND ALL OF THE FINER ITEMS,
I GOTTA GET DOWN
WITH SOME BUFFALO WINGS.
RIGHT ON.
BUT OF COURSE YOU'RE NOT
JUST GONNA LET BUFFALO WINGS
JUST GO THE WAY THEY ARE.
COMIN' UP...
TEN WINGS,
BUFFALO STYLE.
WE'RE FINDIN' OUT WHAT THEY'RE
DOIN' TO THEIR WINGS.
IT'S AWESOME. IT'S NICE
AND CRISPY, WELL COOKED.
YOU HAVE A LICENSE
TO DO THIS?
NOT YET.
THE WAY THEY'RE COOKIN'
AT SCULLY'S TAVERN IN MIAMI...
BLACKENED DOLPHIN.
PUTS A WHOLE NEW SPIN
ON BAR FOOD.
CAN WE GET ONE ESCARGOT?
THOSE ARE
THE ESCARGOT?
EXCELLENT.
GOURMET FOOD
IN A DARK BAR.
BLEU BURGER, NO FRIES.
BUT EVEN THEIR
BAR FOOD CLASSICS...
CHILI CHEESEBURGER.
ARE DONE THE SCULLY'S WAY.
TEN WINGS.
(Guy) I MEAN, I'VE HAD
WINGS ANY WAY TO SUNDAY.
BUT I HAVE NEVER FRIED THEM
AND THEN GRILLED THEM.
BUT THAT'S WHAT SCULLY'S OWNER
CHRIS HIRSH IS DOING.
AND WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
THE ORIENTAL WINGS?
THE GARLIC BUFFALO.
THE SCAMPI WINGS,
AND IT'S AWESOME.
ALL WITH SAUCE DONE CHRIS' WAY.
TEN WINGS,
BUFFALO STYLE.
BUFFALO WINGS ARE HOT SAUCE
AND BUTTER AND THAT'S IT.
BUT I'M READY TO WATCH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A GALLON OF HOT SAUCE.
HALF GALLON
OF WORCESTERSHIRE.
FRESH-CHOPPED GARLIC
WITH WHIPPED BUTTER.
ROASTER WINGS. THEY'RE ALL
FRESH ROASTER WINGS.
LIKE A PTERODACTYL.
WE PAR-FRY 'EM.
PUT A CRUNCH ON 'EM.
SO YOU FRY 'EM,
THEN YOU TOSS 'EM.
THEN YOU GRILL 'EM.
THEN YOU GRILL 'EM,
AND THEN YOU EAT 'EM.
I LOVE THE HANDLE.
(mumbling) THAT GOOD WING.
THEY HAVE THAT SMOKY
UNDER FLAVOR--DELICIOUS.
I'VE NEVER TASTE
ANY WINGS LIKE THIS.
OR THIS.
SCAMPI WINGS.
SCAMPI WINGS--TAKE OUR
SMASHED AND CRUSHED GARLIC,
CHOPPED GARLIC--
NO OIL IN THE PAN?
NOT YET.
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'VE SEEN THIS.
OR THE SAUTE
WITH THE FINGER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
WE'RE GONNA
CARAMELIZE THAT.
NOW YOU START TO ADD
OUR BUTTER.
YOU LET THAT SLOWLY
MELT DOWN?
YOU GOT IT.
HOW ARE OUR
WINGS LOOKIN'?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
CRISPY?
JUST GRILL 'EM UP.
GIVE 'EM A LITTLE FLAVOR.
SAUCE IS READY?
LET'S DO IT.
OH, WOW, YOU
CAN SMELL 'EM.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
AND THAT'S IT.
PROBABLY GONNA GET
KICKED OUT OF THE NATIONAL
WING EATING CLUB.
SACRILEGE.
I WOULD HAVE JUST DONE IT
WITH REGULAR GARLIC,
BUT THE KICKER IS
THE CARAMELIZED GARLIC.
THAT'S SOME LEGIT FOOD,
BROTHER.
LEGIT. LEGIT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
GOT A CARD SPECIAL--
BLEU BURGER.
I'VE HAD EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU.
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA
BE DISAPPOINTED.
(woman) THE BIG THING THAT
MAKES THIS PLACE WORK
IS CHRIS AND CASS.
THEY'RE GREAT.
THIS IS AWESOME.
PEOPLE JUST LOVE IT
AND THEY KEEP COMING.
A JOINT THAT'S GOT
TWO POOL TABLES.
PEOPLE WOULD CALL IT
A SPORTS BAR,
AND YOU'RE
SERVING ESCARGOT.
FANTASTIC, DUDE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
I WARMED UP ON, LIKE, FOUR
OR FIVE BOWLS OF GRANOLA.
THANK YOU.