HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
EVERYBODY COMES HERE.
TWICE A WEEK.
NEIGHBORHOOD JOINTS.
ALL FRESH AND HOMEMADE.
A SIZZLING SPOT IN ST. LOUIS...
THE SCHNITZEL
AND SPAETZLE?
WITH A MENU FROM EVERYWHERE...
(man) ARIZONA PLATE.
(Guy) THIS IS
A GOURMET TAVERN.
NO, IT'S NOT YOUR AVERAGE
PUB GRUB, THAT'S FOR SURE.
AND A CHEF
WHO DOES THINGS HIS WAY.
BRING IT.
THE VIRGINIA HANGOUT...
ANY CRAVING I HAVE,
I'M LIKE,
THE VILLAGE'LL HAVE IT.
WITH A REAL-DEAL CALZONE,
AND EVEN THE CHIPS
ARE MADE FROM SCRATCH.
THEY'RE FRESH,
AND IT'S GOOD SALSA.
THE ARIZONA JOINT...
IT'S GOOD.
IT GETS THE MOUTH GOIN'.
WITH AWARD-WINNING BARBECUE...
(man) THE RIBS
ARE REALLY GOOD.
GREAT FLAVOR,
AND THEY'RE VERY TENDER.
DONE EVERY WHICH WAY...
YOU GOT THE WHOLE FARM
ON HERE, OR WHAT?
AND SUNDAE.
PORK SUNDAE--YUM.
MY KIND OF DESSERT.
AND THE NEIGHBORHOOD DINER
IN A SUBURB OF PHILLY...
MADE TO ORDER
WHERE YOU GET YOUR OWN CUP...
THIS IS MY CUP RIGHT HERE.
TO WASH DOWN
YOUR LOCAL FAVORITES.
SCRAPPLE.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S
IN SCRAPPLE?
IT'S EVERYTHING
BUT THE OINK.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
IN THE SOUTHERN-MOST PART
OF ST. LOUIS,
ABOUT 1/4 MILE
FROM THE MISSISSIPPI RIVER
IS DUTCHTOWN,
A NEIGHBORHOOD LOADED
WITH BRICK 2-STORY FLATS
AND THIS NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE--
IRON BARLEY.
I DID NOT KNOW
WHAT TO EXPECT.
THE FOOD'S SPECTACULAR.
I NEED A STEAK SALAD.
JUST LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE CORNER TAVERN.
THEN YOU WALK IN
AND SEE WHAT FOOD HE HAS,
AND IT'S LIKE, WOW,
IT'S SOMETHIN' ELSE.
SCHNITZEL
AND SPAETZLE?
A MENU THAT YOU
WOULDN'T EXPECT HERE.
LIKE PORK SCALOPPINI, FRESH
MUSSELS IN LEEKS AND CREAM...
OIL'S SMOKIN'.
WE'RE GOIN' IN WITH THE BARELY.
AND THE NAMESAKE GRAIN, BARLEY,
SHOWS UP ALL OVER THE MENU,
LIKE IN THE BARLEY SALAD,
OR THE SEAFOOD BARLEY PAELLA.
THE COOLEST THING
ABOUT THIS PLACE
IS THEY MAKE
EVERYTHING HERE.
(Guy) THIS IS
A GOURMET TAVERN,
NO, IT'S NOT YOUR AVERAGE
PUB GRUB, THAT'S FOR SURE.
PUB GRUB SURE WASN'T THE GOAL
WHEN OWNER TOM COGHILL
WAS PLANNING HIS CAREER.
I WORKED THE WHOLE
HOTEL CIRCUIT.
I WAS CHASIN'
THE STARCHED JACKET.
NO HEADBAND.
NO HEADBAND, BLACK JACKET,
CHECKED PANTS.
ORDER OF MUSSELS UP.
AFTER YEARS AS A CHEF
IN UPSCALE RESTAURANTS
ALL OVER ST. LOUIS,
TOM TOOK A GAMBLE
ALMOST FIVE YEARS AGO...
TAKE THIS ONE UP.
BUYING THIS PLACE
TO RUN HIS WAY...
I NEED SAUCE
FOR THE MEDALLIONS.
AND CRANKIN' OUT
WHATEVER HE FEELS LIKE...
LET ME GET A RISOTTO PLATE.
FROM JUST ABOUT EVERYWHERE,
LIKE A SPANISH SEAFOOD STEW
CALLED ZARZEULA.
OH, YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
BE GENEROUS
WITH THE OLIVE OIL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO IN
WITH THE GARLIC,
BUT WE DON'T WANT IT TO BROWN.
ONCE IT BROWNS,
IT'S GONNA GET BITTER.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL?
MARJORAM.
NOW WHY THE MARJORAM?
MARJORAM IS A LITTLE
STRONGER THAN AN OREGANO.
THYME AND CRUSHED
RED PEPPER.
YOU LOVE CRUSHED
YOU KNOW, YOU NEED A LITTLE
STING, A LITTLE ZIP
TO GIVE IT SOMETHIN'.
SALT AND PEPPER.
LET'S GO WITH
THE BAY LEAVES.
I CAN SMELL THE FLAVOR
COMIN' OUT OF THAT.
WE'RE GOIN' TO NOW
CHILI POWDER AND SAFFRON,
BOTTLE OF WHITE WINE.
WELL, SO FAR,
EVERYTHING YOU'VE DONE,
I COULD PUT THIS ON
A FLIP-FLOP, IT'D TASTE GOOD.
WE'LL ADD THE CHICKEN STOCK,
THEN WE'LL ADD
OUR DICED TOMATOES.
THE SEAFOOD GOES
IN A SEPARATE POT--
FISH, MUSSELS,
CLAMS AND SHRIMP.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA WANT
12 OUNCES OF THE SOUP HERE.
WE'RE GONNA FIRE IT UP.
HOW LONG WILL THAT GO DOWN?
WHEN THE BROTH'S HOT, IT ONLY
TAKES A COUPLE MINUTES,
BUT WE WANT--THESE CLAMS
ARE KINDA BIG RIGHT NOW.
WE NEED THEM TO OPEN UP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR SQUID AND OLIVES.
I'M GONNA
SHUT OFF THE HEAT,
'CAUSE WE DON'T WANT
RUBBER BANDS WITH SQUID.
LITTLE WAGON WHEEL PASTA.
OOH, HOW'D WE FARE?
REAL TASTY.
NICE MIX BETWEEN A CIOPPINO
AND A BOUILLABAISSE.
LITTLE MORE SPICE.
LITTLE MORE ZIP.
MMM, IT JUST MAKES YOU
WANT TO EAT MORE.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
MORE THAN ALL RIGHT, MAN.
THAT'S GOOD EATS.
GOOD EATS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD.
YOU CAN GET JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING AND IT'S JUST--
IT'S JUST
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
LIKE THIS GERMAN FAVORITE--
SPAETZLE.
IT'S ACTUALLY A GERMAN PASTA
THAT'S MADE WITH, UH,
FLOUR, EGGS, SALT,
PEPPER AND NUTMEG.
SEE, I'M JUST
PUSHIN' IT THROUGH?
(Guy) YEP.
AND AFTER, I JUST DROP IT
INTO THE WATER.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS
COME TO A BOIL,
THEN OUR SPAETZLE
WILL BE DONE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DROP
IT INTO THE ICE WATER.
STOP THE COOKING PROCESS.
THE SPAETZLE IS SERVED
WITH ANOTHER TRADITIONAL
GERMAN FAVORITE.
SCHNITZEL.
THE SCHNITZEL WAS
THE FIRST THING THAT I SAW
WHEN I CAME IN
THIS EVENING.
THE SCHNITZEL
AND SPAETZLE?
I ORDER IT EVERY
TIME I'M HERE.
OUR PORK TENDERLOIN--
ABOUT 2 OUNCES.
POUNDING TIME.
FLOUR, EGG WASH,
BREADCRUMBS.
SEASON IT AT ALL?
WHEN IT'S IN THE SKILLET.
OLIVE OIL.
SALT, PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
NOW THIS IS BROWN,
SOME WHITE WINE.
AUNTIE EM?
MAITRE D' BUTTER.
THIS IS LEMON AND GARLIC,
PARSLEY.
HOT.
I GOTTA TELL YA,
THE SCHNITZEL...
I THINK THAT BUTTER THAT
YOU FINISHED IT OFF WITH--
GET A LITTLE HINT
OF THAT LEMON.
THIS IS ALL YOU NEED TO HAVE ON
THE MENU, IN MY OPINION, DUDE.
THE FOOD
IS CONSISTENTLY GOOD.
I'VE NEVER COME HERE
AND HAD A BAD MEAL.
ALL DONE TOM'S WAY,
FROM FINE TO FUNKY.
THIS IS OUR
BALLISTIC ELVIS SAMMICH--
TEXAS TOAST,
CHUNKY PEANUT BUTTER,
STRAWBERRY JAM
AND AMERICAN CHEESE
AND SOME CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
THAT'S THE BALLISTIC PART.
DOES IT GET A WHOLE BANANA?
THAT'S A WHOLE BANANA.
I EAT THIS SANDWICH
ABOUT THREE TIMES A YEAR.
NO.
I'VE GOT A LACK OF
CHOLESTEROL THING GOIN',
AND I'M WORKIN' ON THAT.
AND FOR TOM'S OAK-ROASTED PORK,
HE'S USING
A HOME-BUILT SMOKER.
EVERYTHING HERE
CAME OFF OF A SEMI--
ONE WAS A GAS TANK,
ONE WAS AN OIL TANK.
AND HE'S GOT HIS OWN WAY
OF PREPPING THE MEAT...
WOW.
SEE THAT?
BRING IT.
AS THOUGH YOU'VE BEEN DOIN'
THAT YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
I'M OFTEN INTO
DISMEMBERING THINGS
WITH RANDOM SAWS OF FUN.
THEN WE WANT TO TIE IT UP SO
IT'S NICE, PLUMP AND ROUND.
GET A NICE ROUND EYE ON IT.
THEN WE'LL RUB 'EM DOWN.
WITH MORE THAN A DOZEN
SEASONINGS INCLUDING CAYENNE,
BROWN SUGAR,
CORIANDER AND GINGER.
AND WE'RE SMOKIN'.
LOOK AT THOSE BAD BOYS.
WE'RE RIDING A REAL
GOOD MID-WELL, HERE.
IT'S SERVED
ON A HOT IRON SKILLET
OVER A BED OF TOASTED BARLEY
AND GRILLED VEGETABLES.
THAT'S TENDER.
YEAH.
THAT'S REALLY TENDER.
I MEAN, WITHOUT TAKING
ANY TEMPERATURE ON IT,
AND YOU GOT THAT DOWN
TO THAT KIND OF A SCIENCE.
YEAH.
AND TOM'S WEIRD SCIENCE
IS KEEPING THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT PACKED.
A SIDE OF MASHED WITH THAT,
THAT'S A SANDWICH.
I WANTED A SMALL,
LITTLE PLACE, YOU KNOW?
JUST ENOUGH I COULD DO
WHAT I WANT TO DO,
HAVE A LITTLE FUN, AND WHAT'S
EXPLODED HAS REALLY AMAZED ME.
THE FOOD'S SPECTACULAR.
IT'S A GREAT RESTAURANT,
GREAT PEOPLE.
(Tom) PEOPLE THINK,
OH, I'D LIKE TO HAVE
MY OWN LITTLE PLACE HERE SO
MY FRIENDS AND FAMILY CAN COME.
OKAY, BUT YOU GOTTA REMEMBER,
WHEN THEY SHOW UP,
THEY WANT SOMETHIN' FREE.
UP NEXT...
THAT'S SUPER, MAN.
PIZZA DOUGH FROM SCRATCH,
CALZONES LIKE UP NORTH...
YOU'VE BEEN AROUND
CALZONES BEFORE, RIGHT?
I'M FROM PHILADELPHIA.
I SHOULD BE.
AT A NEIGHBORHOOD HANGOUT
IN VIRGINIA.
HOW DOES IT STACK UP?
DELICIOUS. DELICIOUS.
SO WHEN YOU'RE ROLLIN'
THROUGH RICHMOND, VIRGINIA,
AND YOU ASK THE LOCALS, "HEY,
WHERE DO YOU LIKE TO HANG?"
MOST OF 'EM WILL SEND YOU TO
THIS PLACE--THE VILLAGE CAFE.
PART DIVE, PART BAR,
BUT ALL NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT.
THEY'VE BEEN SERVIN' UP
GOOD EATS TO THIS TOWN
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
MARK YOUR PLATTER.
(Guy) HOLY MOLY STROMBOLI.
THE FOOD'S GOOD,
AND IT'S OPEN LATE.
IT'S RIGHT NEXT TO CAMPUS.
(woman) IT'S REALLY
A FUN PLACE TO HANG OUT.
THAT'S SUPER, MAN.
YOU SHOULD HAVE, LIKE, A
CHEF BOYARDEE HAT ON AND STUFF.
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
THIS PLACE IS EVERYTHING
YOU'D EXPECT
FROM A COLLEGE HANGOUT.
GOOD PRICES.
IT'S CONVENIENT.
BUT IT'S REAL FOOD--
ALMOST ALL FROM SCRATCH.
FRESH AND HOMEMADE.
OH, THIS TASTES GOOD.
8 OUNCE, MEDIUM WELL,
WEARIN' PROVOLONE.
OWNER JOSH RUEGER'S BEEN
RUNNIN' THE PLACE
SINCE HIS DAD BOUGHT IT
A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO.
CHICKEN SALAD CROISSANT.
(Guy) YOU WORK, UH,
HOW MANY DAYS A WEEK?
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
I LIKE EVERYTHING.
STARTED ON THE HOMEMADE FOOD,
MAKIN' IT ALL THE TIME.
FROM CHICKEN PESTO PASTA
TO HOMEMADE MEATLOAF,
TO FRESH PIZZA DOUGH STUFFED
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING
CALLED CALZONES.
THROW IN HOMEMADE RED SAUCE,
AND THEY CALL IT STROMBOLI.
THAT'S A 'ZONE,
AND THIS IS--
ONE 'ZONE, ONE 'BOLI.
THAT'S YUMMY.
IT'S ONE OF OUR BESTSELLERS
WE HAVE HERE.
(Guy) SO HOW OFTEN
DO WE MAKE DOUGH?
EVERY OTHER DAY.
YOU MAKE THE STROMBOLI
AND THE PIZZA OUT OF THIS ALSO?
MM-HMM.
GOOD. WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
RICOTTA MIX
FOR THE CHEESE CALZONE.
NOT JUST RICOTTA,
BUT A RICOTTA MIX?
OUR OWN MIX THAT WE MAKE--
RICOTTA CHEESE, PARMESAN CHEESE,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
OREGANO, BASIL
AND WHITE PEPPER
AND LAST IS MILK.
NOW DO YOU LET THIS SET UP?
IT GETS REFRIGERATED
FOR ABOUT 12 TO 15 HOURS.
AND THAT'LL BE ONE
OF THE MAIN INGREDIENTS
THAT GOES INSIDE THE 'ZONE.
YES.
I LIKE IT.
WE'VE GOT OUR RICOTTA MIX,
MOZZARELLA CHEESE,
FILLING--ITALIAN SAUSAGE,
ONIONS AND GREEN PEPPER.
A LITTLE MORE CHEESE
ON TOP?
A LITTLE BIT MORE
CHEESE ON TOP.
BUT NO SAUCE INSIDE?
NO SAUCE.
SAUCE ON THE SIDE.
SAUCE IS ON THE SIDE.
WE DID THAT IN HARMONY.
THAT'S A BIG CALZONE.
FOUR SLITS.
AND YOU DO
THE SLITS BECAUSE...
STEAM.
SO YOU GET NICE,
CRISP DOUGH?
I DIG IT, AND THE TEMPERATURE
OF THE OVEN IS AT...
ABOUT 550.
WOW, HARD AND FAST.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
WHAT'S YOUR LAST NAME?
RUEGER.
THAT'S NOT ITALIAN.
NO, IT'S NOT.
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKIN'
ITALIAN, BUDDY--
NICE DOUGH., PERFECT COLOR.
TAKE A LOOKY, WOOKIEE.
DRIP TEST.
IT'S GONNA BE HOT.
IT'S NOT GONNA BE TOO BAD.
LIAR.
I DON'T SEE YOU
PICKIN' UP A PIECE.
OW! OW! OW!
IT'S CRISPY,
BIG FLAVOR.
THAT RICOTTA SAUCE
THAT YOU MAKE--
VERY SIMPLE
BUT EXTREMELY DELICIOUS.
DUDE, IF THE REST OF THE FOOD
YOU MAKE IS LIKE THAT,
YOU BETTER THINK
ABOUT EXPANDING.
IT'S FRESH AND IT'S
BAKED TO ORDER.
(Guy) YOU'VE BEEN AROUND
CALZONES BEFORE, RIGHT?
I'M FROM PHILADELPHIA.
I SHOULD BE.
WELL, HOW DOES IT STACK UP?
DELICIOUS. DELICIOUS.
THEY'RE HOME-MAKIN' PIZZAS
FROM THE SAME DOUGH...
SPAGHETTI.
AND SERVIN'
ALL KINDS OF PASTA.
(woman) THE VEGGIE SPAGHETTI
IS LOADED WITH EVERYTHING,
AND IT'S SO GOOD.
BUT IT AIN'T JUST ITALIAN.
(man) I ENJOY EATIN'
BLACK BEANS AND RICE,
WHICH I'D ORIGINALLY
EAT IN NEW ORLEANS.
THERE'S HOMEMADE
MIDDLE EASTERN HUMMUS
AND EVEN THE CHIPS AND SALSA
ARE MADE FROM SCRATCH.
THEY'RE FRESH, AND THE SALSA
ACTUALLY DOESN'T TASTE
LIKE IT CAME FROM A CAN,
IT TASTES REALLY,
REALLY FRESH.
YOU CAN JUST
TELL THE DIFFERENCE.
JOSH SAYS MOST OF THE RECIPES
CAME WITH THE RESTAURANT.
PICK IT UP!
THEY'VE ADDED A FEW,
BUT STAYED FOCUSED ON KEEPING
EVERYTHING FRESH AND HOMEMADE.
HEY, GUYS, MUSHROOM AND MUENSTER
CROISSANT WITH ONION RINGS.
HOW 'BOUT THE ONION RINGS?
I ALWAYS GET THEM.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
WHERE'D YOU GET THE RECIPE?
MADE IT.
CAME UP WITH IT--
GOLDEN GRIFFIN ALE BEER...
WAY TO THROW THEIR PLUG.
PLAYER.
MARGARINE AND CANOLA OIL
BLENDED TOGETHER,
MALT VINEGAR.
MMM. EGGS, SHELL AND ALL?
NO, NO SHELLS.
NO SHELLS.
NOW I'VE SEEN PEOPLE
DO THIS REALLY FAST.
I'M NOT THAT FAST.
DON'T PUT US TO SLEEP.
NOW THE DRY.
WHAT DO WE HAVE IN THE DRY?
FLOUR, SALT, BAKING POWDER.
AERATES IT
AND LEAVENS IT, OKAY.
CORNSTARCH--
THAT'S A TINY BIT
OF CORNSTARCH.
YES, IT IS.
BLACK PEPPER.
CAYENNE PEPPER.
LITTLE BIT OF HEAT,
LITTLE BIT OF COLOR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY.
THAT NOISE IS PLEASANT.
NOW WHERE DID YOU LEARN
THESE TECHNIQUES?
SPIN THE BOWL, WORK THE--
WHERE'D YOU LEARN THAT?
IT COMES NATURAL.
THIS IS NATURAL
BLOND, TOO.
A SPECIAL DRILL HERE.
RUN HER FULL THROTTLE, LUKE!
SOUNDS LIKE
"TEXAS CHAINSAW MASSACRE"
MEETS A RESTAURANT.
(imitates chainsaw motor)
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE GONNA
SHEETROCK THE WHOLE HOUSE.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKIN' BATTER.
ARE CHIPS
GOOD IN THAT, TOO?
YES, SIR.
CUT 'EM EVERY DAY?
CUT 'EM EVERY DAY.
THEY SMELL FRESH.
MAKE MY EYES WATER.
IN THE FLOUR?
IN THE FLOUR.
I LIKE HOW YOU ALLOW ME
TO DO THE WORK.
I'LL LET YOU DO THAT.
YOU'LL LET ME
DO THIS PART?
GOOD-LOOKIN' BATTER, MAN.
STICKIN' RIGHT TO IT.
WHEN YOU COOK AN ORDER
OF--OF RINGS,
I MEAN, IT'S A--
SOMEONE'S GOTTA BE ON POINT.
YEAH, WE DO THIS
EVERY TIME.
THAT HAS, LIKE, A TEMPURA
BATTER LOOK TO IT.
(whistles)
ABOUT 30 SECONDS,
THEN YOU TURN 'EM.
NO THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
RANCH DRESSING.
HERE'S MY FAVORITE.
A LITTLE SPICY RANCH. MMM.
I GET THE BEER
RIGHT IN THE NOSE.
YOU CAN TASTE THE ONION,
BUT IT'S COOKED ALL THE WAY.
AW, THAT'S TASTY, MAN,
I'M GONNA TELL YA.
IT'S A CRUNCHY CRUNCH.
(mumbling)
EXACTLY.
AND IT'S ALL EXACTLY
WHAT FOLKS AROUND HERE
HAVE COME TO EXPECT...
THE FOOD HERE'S AWESOME.
ANY CRAVING I HAVE, I'M LIKE,
"THE VILLAGE'LL HAVE IT."
CALZONE WITH PEPPERONI.
AT THE PLACE THAT'S BEEN
THE HANGOUT IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
FOR A HALF A CENTURY.
TWICE A WEEK.
TWICE A WEEK?
THIS IS SOMEWHAT HOME.
SO IT'S LIKE, "HEY, WHERE
DO YOU WANT TO GO FOR LUNCH?"
"LET'S GO TO THE VILLAGE."
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST, THAT'S IT.
EVERYBODY COMES HERE.
(mumbling)
THIS IS NICE AND LIGHT.
(continues mumbling)
EXCELLENT.
GLAD YOU SAID THAT.
COMING UP...
(Guy) LOOK AT THAT.
A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
IN ARIZONA...
(man) I LOVE THE RIBS.
I LIKE THE CHICKEN.
I LIKE THE ONION RINGS.
ANYTHING YOU DON'T LIKE?
NO.
WHERE THIS GUY
WILL BARBECUE ANYTHING.
I'VE NEVER HAD BARBECUE TURKEY.
THIS IS A FIRST.
SOMETHIN'S
A LITTLE STRANGE HERE.
JOINT LOOKS LIKE A DINER,
BUT IT'S IN GLENDALE, ARIZONA.
OH, YEAH, AND THEY'RE SERVING
SOUTHERN-STYLE BARBECUE,
YOU KNOW, LOW AND SLOW.
BUT THEY TELL ME THE GUY
IS A COMPETITIVE
BARBECUE CHAMPION...
WHO'S WON SOME OF THE BIGGEST
COMPETITIONS IN THE COUNTRY.
LET'S SEE,
I'VE GOT 300 AWARDS.
WHAT'S THE MOST PRESTIGIOUS
EVENT YOU WON?
OH, ALWAYS JACK DANIELS.
AND IT'S THOSE SAME RECIPES
THAT HE'S CRANKIN' OUT
FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD CROWD...
GOT THE PORK AND SLAW.
EVERY DAY...
(man) THE RIBS
ARE REALLY GOOD.
GREAT FLAVOR,
AND THEY'RE VERY TENDER.
THE BEEF BRISKET.
IT TASTES REALLY GOOD,
AND IT'S MOIST.
I LOVE THE PULLED PORK.
THE BEST.
ALL DONE LOW AND SLOW IN
ROGER'S MESQUITE-FIRED SMOKER.
THIS IS THE HEART
OF THE BUSINESS.
HE LEARNED HOW TO DO THIS
ALMOST 30 YEARS AGO
AT A JOINT CALLED THEE PITS.
YOU GOT THE WHOLE FARM
ON HERE, OR WHAT?
WHEN HE OPENED A PLACE
OF HIS OWN,
HE CALLED IT THEE PITS AGAIN.
I LOVE THE RIBS.
I LIKE THE CHICKEN WINGS.
I LIKE THE ONION RINGS.
(Guy) SIR, LET'S
MAKE IT EASY.
LET'S GO BACK--
ANYTHING YOU DON'T LIKE?
NO.
AND BEYOND THE CLASSICS...
ORDER UP.
ROGER'S DOING A LOT OF THINGS
YOU DON'T FIND
AT MOST BARBECUE JOINTS.
I LOVE THE PORK SUNDAE
WITH PULLED PORK
AND THEN SOME BEANS--YUM.
MY KIND OF DESSERT.
AND HE'S SMOKIN' SHRIMP.
SO YOU WANT
TO JUST SMOKE IT ENOUGH
TO GIVE IT THAT NICE
MESQUITE-SMOKED FLAVOR.
BUT THEN YOU FINISH IT OFF
ON THE GRILL.
STAND IT RIGHT THERE
ON THE END LIKE THIS.
THAT'S THE GUY LOOK.
I LIKE THAT.
THIS IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
HE'S EVEN SMOKIN' CATFISH.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S REALLY AWESOME.
IT'S GOT A GREAT
SMOKY FLAVOR TO IT.
BUT BEYOND THE SMOKE,
THERE'S THE RUB.
AND THAT'S THE RUB.
TEACH ME THE RUB,
OH, WISE ONE.
SEASONED SALT,
SPANISH PAPRIKA.
IT'S GOT A-A DIFFERENT--
LITTLE DIFFERENT TASTE
THAT REGULAR PAPRIKA.
I TOSS IN A LITTLE SUGAR...
LITTLE SUGAR.
LITTLE GRANULATED GARLIC,
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN
AND ALSO A LITTLE SALT.
A LITTLE ONION.
A LITTLE ONION,
SOME PAPRIKA--
THAT--
PARSLEY. PARSLEY.
'CAUSE IF YOUR PAPRIKA'S
LOOKIN' LIKE THAT,
THAT'S WHY I'M NOT WINNIN'
BIG COMPETITIONS.
I'VE BEEN THINKIN'
IT'S PARSLEY THE WHOLE TIME.
AND THEN WE HAVE MY INGREDIENT
HERE THAT I ADD.
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT HALF OF ONE
AND THEN HALF OF YOUR SECRET.
SO...
YEAH, NOW YOU'RE
CALCULATING.
WHO GETS TO MAKE
THE RUB HERE?
I DO.
ONLY YOU.
YEAH.
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
THAT MAKES THE RUB.
I'M THE ONLY ONE
AND THAT GOES
ON EVERYTHING?
EVERYTHING.
AND YOU'RE NOT WORRIED ABOUT
EVERYTHING HAVING A SIMILAR--
NO, IT DOESN'T.
I'VE USED THIS
IN COMPETITIONS.
I'VE WON CHICKEN.
I'VE WON RIBS.
I'VE WON SHOULDERS.
IT'S VERY VERSATILE.
HE'S EVEN SMOKIN'
WHOLE TURKEYS WITH IT.
I'VE NEVER HAD BARBEQUED TURKEY.
THIS IS A FIRST.
HOW DO YOU SERVE THIS?
WE PULL IT.
ALL PULLED BIRD.
ALL PULLED.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
THIS IS MARGARINE
TO GIVE IT A GLAZE.
IT ALSO LETS
THE SEASONING ADHERE TO IT.
GIVE IT THE OLD RUB,
TAKE THIS BEAUTY
AND JUST LAY HER RIGHT IN.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THAT GONNA RUN FOR?
USUALLY A BIRD THIS SIZE WILL
TAKE ABOUT, UH, 14 HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
MMM. OH, MAN.
BUT IT SURE IS
TENDER TURKEY.
OH, YEAH.
YOU TALKIN' TO ME?
REALLY, REALLY GOOD
MOIST TURKEY.
VERY TENDER.
AND GREAT WITH
ROGER'S HOMEMADE SAUCE.
SAUCE IS MONEY.
I START OFF
WITH BROWN SUGAR,
A MIXTURE OF WHICH THE MAIN BULK
IS WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
AND WHAT ELSE
IS IN THERE?
COUPLE ITEMS IN THERE THAT'S
JUST KIND OF MY LITTLE SECRET.
JUST LIKE THE RUB.
YOU'RE GONNA GIVE ME
EVERYTHING BUT TWO?
WELL, YEAH, YOU GOTTA
GIVE A LITTLE BIT.
I MEAN, YOU GOT
THE MAJORITY.
THEN I'LL PUT
IN THE MUSTARD.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT MUCH
MUSTARD GO IN SAUCE.
OH, YEAH.
WANT ME TO HELP?
YEAH, THAT'D BE GREAT.
HEINZ KETCHUP
IS WHAT I USE.
NO COOKIN' IT.
NO MESSIN' WITH IT.
THAT'S GOOD SAUCE.
AND FOLKS HERE SAY
IT'S GREAT ON EVERYTHING--
RIBS...
IT JUST HAS
A GOOD FLAVOR TO IT.
BRISKET...
TANGY, BUT NOT TOO MUCH.
AND OF COURSE...
NUMBER-ONE-SELLING ITEM
ON THE MENU?
PULLED PORK.
PULLED PORK HANDS DOWN,
NO QUESTION.
80%.
I HAD SOME PULLED PORK,
BUT I ALREADY ATE IT.
OH, YEAH, IT'S 'CAUSE
YOU'RE GOING IN CYCLES.
(woman) THE SAD THING IS,
ONCE HAD THE PULLED PORK,
THAT'S, LIKE,
THE ONLY THING I WANTED.
(Guy) THAT'S IT?
THAT'S THE STAPLE?
YEAH.
IT'S GOOD. IT' GETS--
GETS THE MOUTH GOIN'.
LIKE EVERYTHING
ROGER'S SMOKING,
GRILLING AND MIXING UP.
HE JUST, SOMEHOW OR ANOTHER,
JUST HAS THE MAGIC ABOUT HIM.
AND HE CAN DO IT.
I THINK HE JUST, YOU KNOW,
EATS IT, SLEEPS IT
AND DREAMS IT.
HERE'S YOUR
PULLED TURKEY.
I KNOW YOU'VE WON A LOT, A LOT,
A LOT, A LOT OF COMPETITIONS,
BUT YOU'VE WON
SO MANY COMPETITIONS
THAT YOU START TO
STORE THE OLD TROPHIES
ON TOP OF THE SMOKER?
YEAH, WELL,
I'VE GOT SOME THERE.
I'VE GOT SOME IN THE BOTTOM.
I'VE GOT SOME AT HOME.
I JUST DON'T HAVE
ANY PLACE TO PUT 'EM.
HE'S A CHAMP.
HE'S A CHAMP IN OUR EYES.
AND THE REST
OF THE WORLD'S.
YEAH.
WELL DONE.
NOW I KNOW WHY YOU'VE BEEN
IN SO MANY COMPETITIONS,
WHY YOU WON SO MANY.
REAL DEAL.
UP NEXT...
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
WE'RE IN A SUBURB
OF PHILADELPHIA
FOR SOMETHING
CALLED SCRAPPLE.
(man) FOR PEOPLE
IN THIS AREA,
SCRAPPLE IS LIKE
A FINE WINE.
AND THE ULTIMATE TASTE TEST.
CAN I GET THE THIN SLICE
IN THE FRYER FOR,
LIKE, FOUR DAYS?
WE'RE HERE
IN HATBORO, PENNSYLVANIA,
WHICH IS RIGHT
OUTSIDE OF PHILLY,
AT A DINER THAT
WAS BUILT IN 1953.
IT'S BEEN A DINER,
A CHINESE RESTAURANT,
AND NOW IT'S HOME TO DADDYPOPS,
A PLACE THAT'S GOT BARBER STOOLS
AT THE COUNTER,
CUSTOMERS' COFFEE CUPS
ON THE WALLS
AND A PENNSYLVANIA SPECIALTY
CALLED SCRAPPLE.
IN THIS AREA,
SCRAPPLE IS LIKE A FINE WINE.
IT'S PORK SCRAPS
AND CORNMEAL...
OH, I LOVE SCRAPPLE.
IT'S NOT GOOD FOR YA,
BUT I LOVE IT.
IT'S EVERYTHING
BUT THE OINK.
AS MUCH OF A LOCAL HABIT
AS THE DINER ITSELF.
I'VE NEVER FOUND ONE AS WARM
AND AS FRIENDLY AS DADDYPOPS.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
A NEIGHBORHOOD INSTITUTION
FILLED WITH REGULARS WHO
KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THEY WANT...
DADDYPOPS HAS THE BEST
BREAKFAST EVER.
(man) IT'S GOT LIKE BACON CRISPS
AND EGGS OVER-LIGHT,
AND MY HOME FRIES
HAVE TO HAVE ONIONS IN IT.
MADE TO ORDER.
AND EVERYONE
MADE TO FEEL AT HOME...
THIS IS MY CUP RIGHT HERE.
BY 21-YEAR OWNER KEN SMITH.
THOSE ARE ALL
MY EVERYDAY CUSTOMER MUGS.
A CUSTOMER COMES IN AND ALWAYS
ASKS FOR A HALF A CUP.
(Guy) NUTTY DAVE. HOW LONG
YOU BEEN COMIN' HERE?
(man) A YEAR.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
IS IT THE SERVICE
OR THE FOOD?
BOTH.
"PHILLY'S PHATTEST FOOD."
PHAT--"P-H."
WHAT WE'RE KNOWN FOR
IS OUR HOME FRIES.
THEY'RE ABSOLUTELY THE BEST.
FIRST OF ALL,
THERE'S LOTS OF 'EM.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF POTATOES
DO WE GO THROUGH IN A DAY?
150, 200.
ALL FRESH CUT
AND MADE TO ORDER.
WHAT DO THEY GET FRIED IN?
ALL BUTTER.
THERE'S NO BETTER WAY
TO DO IT.
I EAT AT DINERS EVERYWHERE,
AND I HAVE NEVER, EVER
COME CLOSE TO A POTATO
THAT TASTES LIKE THIS.
BUT THE REAL TREAT
FOR THE LOCALS?
SCRAPPLE.
WELL, SCRAPPLE'S A PRODUCT
OF THE THIS AREA.
IT'S A LOAF--ALL THE SCRAP
PARTS OF A--OF A PIG.
I THINK IT'S PIG'S FEET.
EVERYTHING BUT THE SQUEAL.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT'S IN SCRAPPLE?
I'VE HEARD, AND I JUST
PUT IT OUT OF MY MIND.
YOU JUST PUT IT OUT OF YOUR
MIND. ARE WE FRYING THIS?
WE WANT TO SHOW YOU
BOTH WAYS.
(Guy) OKAY.
SOME PEOPLE WANT IT GRILLED.
MOST PEOPLE GET IT DEEP FRIED.
YOU DEEP-FRY IT WITH
A HARD CRUST ON THE OUTSIDE.
ALL RIGHT, PIG PARTS
DONE TWO WAYS.
BUT HOW DO YOU CHOOSE?
I WANT TO HAVE A BLIND
TASTING OF THE SCRAPPLE.
I AM READY. OH.
FROM THAT BITE, I FEEL THAT I
HAD HOOF, EAR AND TONGUE.
TELL ME WHICH SCRAPPLE
YOU LIKE THE BEST.
THE FIRST ONE WAS THE THIN CUT
FOR THE FLATTOP.
AND THE SECOND ONE
WAS THE FRYER.
YOU TRY IT WITH SYRUP?
TASTES LIKE FRENCH TOAST.
PHILLY NEIGHBORHOOD STYLE
AND A PLACE OF HONOR
FOR YOUR COFFEE CUP.
AND IT'S ON THE MUG WALL.
THIS IS MY KIND OF PLACE.
CAN I GET THE THIN SLICE IN
THE FRYER FOR, LIKE, FOUR DAYS?
FOR FOUR DAYS.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FROM SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'M GONNA STAND BACK.
WOW, MY TEETH ARE LOOSE.
I WANT TO PLAY
HERE MORE.