HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
ORDER UP. GET 'EM
WHILE THEY'RE HOT.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THIS IS
AN INSTITUTION IN TOWN.
WHERE YOU COME.
WHERE THE LOCALS GO.
NO QUESTION
WHERE WE'RE GOING.
WE JUST SAY,
"SEE YOU THERE."
OUTSIDE ATLANTA...
THIS IS GOOD, I'M TELLING YOU.
AIN'T NOTHING LIKE IT.
A REAL SOUTHERN TRADITION...
THE FOOD
IS ALWAYS COUNTRY FOOD.
(whistles)
GOOD STUFF, MAN.
HALF A CENTURY,
AND STILL GOING STRONG.
THANK YOU.
EVERYBODY
KNOWS EVERYBODY.
GOOD TO SEE Y'ALL.
WE CHANGE BY STAYING THE SAME.
LET EVERYBODY ELSE CHANGE.
IN ALBUQUERQUE...
I AM
A STEAK EATER.
BIG BEEF...
GOING ON?
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU TO GOT TO KNOW
HOW TO FIND...
DON'T BE AFRAID
WHEN YOU SEE THE ENTRANCE.
'CAUSE IT'S
BEHIND THE LIQUOR STORE.
WHEN YOU GET INSIDE,
YOU'LL BE VERY SURPRISED.
THAT IS GREAT.
AND A JOINT
JUST OUTSIDE NEW ORLEANS...
IT'S JUST BEEN HERE FOREVER.
IT'S JUST LIKE A LANDMARK.
WHERE THEY'RE DOING
BAR FOOD THEIR WAY.
(imitating Elmer Fudd) BE VEWY,
VEWY QUIET. I'M TWYING WABBIT.
(normal voice)
THAT IS OUTSTANDING.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
IT'S ONLY 10 MILES FROM ATLANTA,
BUT WHEN YOU CRUISE DOWN MAIN
STREET HERE IN TUCKER, GEORGIA,
WELL, IT LOOKS
LIKE IT DID 50 YEARS AGO--
ESPECIALLY THIS LOCAL LANDMARK,
MATTHEWS CAFETERIA,
A THIRD-GENERATION JOINT
WHERE FOLKS SAY
THE FOOD IS BETTER THAN EVER.
THIS IS GOOD, I'M TELLING YOU.
AIN'T NOTHING LIKE IT.
I'LL HAVE SWEET POTATOES
AND TURNIP GREENS.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS,
PLEASE.
TUESDAY'S GREAT--
FRIED CHICKEN DAY.
MASHED POTATOES
AND GREEN BEANS, PLEASE.
THIS IS
AN INSTITUTION IN TOWN.
WHERE YOU COME.
ENJOY YOUR BREAKFAST,
GUYS.
EVERYBODY
KNOWS EVERYBODY,
SO YOU GET
A REAL SMALL-TOWN FEEL.
GOOD TO SEE Y'ALL.
AT THE KIND
OF SMALL-TOWN CAFETERIA
THE SOUTH
USED TO BE FULL OF.
THANK YOU.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S ALWAYS GREAT.
JUST GOOD
HOME COOKING.
THIS IS A DYING BREED.
SOUTHERN FOOD,
FOR ONE THING...
(Guy) RIGHT.
AND DOING IT THE RIGHT WAY
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
'CAUSE THAT'S THE WAY
MICHAEL GREENE GREW UP...
ARE YOU READY?
WORKING HERE NEXT TO HIS
DAD CHARLES AND HIS MOM ALICE.
IT WAS YOUR DAD
THAT STARTED THIS.
(Alice) YES.
WHO'S RUNNING
THE SHOW THESE DAYS?
MICHAEL.
YOU'RE IN CHARGE?
YEAH.
SO IT'S HIS TURN TO MAKE SURE
EVERYONE'S GETTING
EXACTLY WHAT THEY EXPECT.
HOW'S YOUR BISCUIT?
GOOD, GOOD.
(man) FINE, FINE.
AND THEY'RE STILL HOMEMADE
EVERY MORNING.
WE'RE GONNA
MEASURE THAT OR--NO.
THAT WAS
3 1/2 POUNDS.
17 1/2 POUNDS
OF SHORTENING.
WE'RE GONNA BREAK THIS UP
INTO SOME PIECES
SO WE CAN WORK 'EM
A LITTLE BETTER.
AND THIS IS WHAT CREATES
THE FLAKINESS OF THE BISCUIT.
YES, SIR.
NONFAT BUTTERMILK?
ISN'T THAT
A CONTRADICTION?
IT'S CULTURED BUTTERMILK,
BUT IT'S FAT-FREE.
WHOO.
I LOVE
THIS MEASURING TECHNIQUE.
I'VE GOT TWO SPOONS
RIGHT HERE. RIGHT HERE.
RIGHT THERE.
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'VE SEEN
THE MAN-SPATULA.
MANTULA.
THAT--IT IS
THE MANTULA.
NO ROLLING PIN.
JUST A LITTLE PATTY-PAT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE JUST
GONNA START CUTTING 'EM OUT.
WE'RE GONNA PUNCH 'EM DOWN.
THERE'S NO WRONG WAY.
JUST GIVE 'EM A SMACK.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT IS MONEY.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT GOOD?
THAT'S FLAKY.
THAT'S A BISCUIT. THAT'S
WHEN YOU WIN WITH A BISCUIT.
THAT'S A TOUCHDOWN
RIGHT THERE.
AND THAT'S EVEN BEFORE
THE SAUSAGE GRAVY.
THAT WOULD BE GOOD
OUT OF A SHOE.
NICE LITTLE PEPPER
IN THERE,
LITTLE--LITTLE
BITE TO IT.
A LOT OF PEPPER.
WHEN IT'S DONE THE RIGHT WAY,
LIKE THAT...
YEP.
YOU DON'T NEED
ANYTHING ELSE.
WE'VE DONE BISCUITS AND GRAVY
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
MM-HMM.
HANDS-DOWN,
ONE OF THE BEST.
THANKS, MAN.
ONE OF THE BEST, DUDE.
SERIOUSLY.
(woman) BISCUIT
WITH SAUSAGE GRAVY.
IT'S ABOUT AS CLOSE TO A
HOMEMADE BISCUIT AS YOU CAN GET.
AND THEY'RE STUFFING
THE SAME BISCUIT
WITH SAUSAGE, CHEESE,
HAM AND BACON,
AND USING THE SAME DOUGH FOR
ANOTHER BIG LOCAL FAVORITE...
TOUCHDOWN.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
WOW.
IF THAT IS NOT THE MOST TENDER
DUMPLING I'VE EVER HAD.
THAT'S A MEAL
RIGHT THERE.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
KIND OF BRINGS BACK HOME
TO HOW MY GRANDMOTHER
USED TO MAKE
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
THE BEST THING ABOUT MATTHEWS
IS IT NEVER CHANGES.
BUT IT AIN'T THE DECOR THAT'S
KEEPING THIS PLACE PACKED.
IT'S ABOUT FOOD.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS
COUNTRY FOOD,
AND THAT'S
WHAT I LIKE.
YESTERDAY,
I ATE HERE THREE TIMES.
IT'S ONE OF THE PLACES--
ONLY PLACES IN TOWN
THAT YOU CAN GET
THESE FRESH VEGETABLES.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO THE SWEET POTATOES THE MOST.
BEST FRIED CHICKEN
IN TOWN.
I LIKE THE GREENS,
AND I LIKE THE BRUNSWICK STEW.
I DON'T KNOW THAT
I'VE HAD BRUNSWICK STEW.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE SOME TODAY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WELL, LET
THE MAGIC HAPPEN.
BUT MOST BRUNSWICK STEW
DOESN'T BEGIN OUT BACK.
I WOULDN'T EXPECT
THAT YOU WOULD BE DOING THINGS
LIKE SMOKING CHICKEN.
FOR STEW, NONETHELESS.
BEAUTIFUL.
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA PULL THE
SKIN OFF AND RESERVE THE SKIN.
PULL THE CHICKEN OFF,
DOESN'T--
WELL, YOU DO IT
WITH BOTH.
SEE, I LIKE THAT YOU DO
EVERYTHING WITH THE BONE,
BECAUSE SO MUCH OF THAT FLAVOR
COMES THROUGH THE MEAT.
WE'RE GONNA CHOP THIS CHICKEN
VERY, VERY FINELY.
WE WANT TO CHOP THE SKIN UP
TO WHERE IT IS...
SUPERFINE.
VIRTUALLY INVISIBLE
IN THE FINISHED PRODUCT, YEAH.
WE'RE GOING TO START
WITH A GOOD CHICKEN BROTH.
OKAY.
THAT'S JUST ENOUGH
DRY MUSTARD RIGHT THERE
TO FINISH THIS ONE.
AGAIN, WE'RE DOING--WE'RE IN THE
SUPER MIKE MEASURING TECHNIQUES.
PERFECT.
THAT WAS IT, MAN.
2 QUARTS
OF CHOPPED TOMATOES,
CHOPPED ONIONS,
CHICKEN SKIN.
IT'S NOT VERY FATTY AT ALL
WHEN YOU COOK IT ON THE SMOKER.
NO, 'CAUSE IT
RENDERS OFF. SURE.
IT RENDERS OFF. IT'S IN THE
BOTTOM OF THE SMOKER RIGHT NOW.
KETCHUP NEXT.
KETCHUP?
OKAY, THIS
IS STRAIGHT UP THERE
WITH THE WEIRDEST THINGS
I'VE EVER SEEN MADE.
REALLY?
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT, 1 CUP.
WAIT A SECOND,
YOU'RE GONNA MEASURE--
YEAH, WE ALWAYS
MEASURE IN THIS.
THAT IS NOT--
THAT'S NOT A CUP.
IT'S 2 CUPS. I'M GONNA DO
HALF OF IT. THAT'LL BE--
ALL RIGHT.
YOUR 2 CUPS
OF WHITE VINEGAR. WHOOP.
TWO BOTTLES
OF HOT SAUCE,
A LITTLE BARBECUE SAUCE,
CREAMED CORN,
AND THIS
IS EXACTLY...
THAT MUCH.
THAT MUCH RIGHT THERE
WE ADMINISTER--
TO THE MAD SCIENTIST
EXPERIMENT.
NOW WE HAVE CREAMED CORN
ADDED TO THIS.
BRING THAT
UP TO A BOIL, SIMMER.
OKAY, WE GOT
SMOKED CHICKEN HERE.
WOW, THAT'S A LOT OF CHICKEN.
AND THIS IS IT.
THIS IS BRUNSWICK STEW.
FIRST,
I GET BARBECUE...
RIGHT.
SMOKINESS...
THEN I GET SOUP, THEN I GET
SPICY AND SOME CHILI,
THEN I GET
BUFFALO WING SAUCE.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S KIND OF LIKE METALLICA
PLAYING WITH THE PHILHARMONIC.
THAT IS CRAZY.
IT'S BRUNSWICK STEW, DUDE,
AND THAT'S IT.
(whistles)
GOOD STUFF, MAN.
IT'S WHAT MINE IS.
BRUNSWICK STEW'S THE BEST
BRUNSWICK STEW I'VE EVER HAD.
GOOD ON A COLD WINTER DAY.
IT'S DYNAMITE.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
A SOUTHERN CLASSIC, LIKE
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING HERE.
YOU CAN SEE THAT THEY TAKE
A LOT OF PRIDE IN PREPARING IT.
HOMEMADE FROM FAMILY RECIPES
FOR MORE THAN 50 YEARS.
HERE'S THE MILLIONAIRES' TABLE
RIGHT HERE.
WE CHANGE BY STAYING THE SAME.
LET EVERYBODY ELSE CHANGE.
NO. IF IT'S NOT BROKEN,
DON'T FIX IT.
I MEAN,
I LOVE THE ATTITUDE.
WHAT A GREAT PLACE.
A LOT OF CHARACTER.
THANK YOU.
WE N-E-E-D A LOT
OF DUMPLINGS.
ARE WE GONNA
S-P-E-L-L EVERYTHING?
N-O.
O-K.
OKAY.
UP NEXT...
(man) STEAKHOUSE,
STEAKHOUSE.
MEAT AND POTATOES PLACE,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
WE'RE HEADING TO NEW MEXICO.
WHEN WHEN I FIRST DROVE UP, I
THOUGHT, YOU GOT TO BE KIDDING.
FOR A BIG BEEF
BEHIND THE LIQUOR STORE.
(Guy) LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT'S JUST GREAT.
OHH.
ONE OF THE THINGS I LOVE ABOUT
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
IS I GET TO VISIT
THE COOLEST PLACES
THAT YOU'D PROBABLY DRIVE BY IF
YOU DIDN'T KNOW WHERE THEY WERE.
LIKE HERE,
IN ALBUQUERQUE, NEW MEXICO,
YOU WANT A GOOD DINNER?
HIT THE LIQUOR STORE, WHERE
YOU'LL FIND A GREAT STEAKHOUSE?
OH, BEHIND THE BEER COOLER,
I GUESS.
WHEN I FIRST DROVE UP, I
THOUGHT, YOU GOT TO BE KIDDING.
DON'T BE AFRAID
WHEN YOU SEE THE ENTRANCE.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE A REAL
RESTAURANT UNTIL YOU GET INSIDE,
AND THEN IT'S AWESOME.
ORDER UP. GET 'EM
WHILE THEY'RE HOT.
THIS IS AN ALBUQUERQUE
INSTITUTION.
I AM A STEAK EATER.
STEAK AND POTATOES.
(man) THE MEAT'S
REALLY GOOD.
THAT IS GREAT.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
THE LOCAL'S PLACE TO COME
AND KIND OF
CHILL ON ROUTE 66.
STEAKHOUSE, STEAKHOUSE. MEAT AND
POTATOES PLACE, THAT'S FOR SURE.
TODAY I'M HAVING THE
GREEN CHILE CHEESE HAMBURGER,
AND I'M ALSO HAVING THE STEAK.
I'M INTO PROTEIN.
AND THEY'VE GOT IT HERE--
BURGERS, STEAKS, RIBS,
EVEN A CHEESESTEAK.
THE RIB SPECIAL.
YOU DON'T COME TO THIS JOINT
FOR A TOMATO AND AVOCADO
ON WHOLE WHEAT.
I NEED
A RIB PLATE.
NO QUESTION WHERE WE'RE GOING.
WE JUST SAY, "SEE YOU THERE."
IT'S GOOD,
AND--AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
MONTE CARLO
IS AN INSTITUTION.
SO'S THE FAMILY
THAT'S BEEN RUNNING IT...
IT'S ALL
WORD-OF-MOUTH.
FOR THREE DECADES.
AND WHAT'S YOUR NICKNAME,
BY THE WAY?
SCREWY LOUIE.
AND THEY'RE STILL
ALL LED BY MAMA.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE MENU.
THIS IS--IT'S ABOUT MAMA.
ANGELINA KATSAROS
STARTED THIS JOINT
WITH HER LATE HUSBAND MIKE.
START FOR THE SANDWICHES.
AFTER TWO, THREE MONTHS,
SOMEBODY COME HERE, SAY, "MIKE,
WHY DON'T YOU PUT A HAMBURGER,
STEAKS AND SOMETHING ELSE?"
1980, RUNNING A GRILL.
WHY HAVE YOU BEEN
COMING HERE SO LONG?
STEAK.
KIND OF JUST THAT'S IT?
THE STEAK.
THE BEST ONE
IN TOWN.
I GOT TO TELL YOU,
I WOULDN'T EXPECT
THAT YOU WOULD BE
CUTTING RIB EYES FRESH.
EVERY DAY.
EVERYTHING.
SIRLOIN.
RIB EYE, NEW YORKS.
THE NEW YORK,
THE RIB EYE.
WHERE DID THAT PHILOSOPHY
COME FROM?
FROM MY FATHER--
FRESH, GOOD FOOD,
THAT'S IT.
THAT WAS
HIS PRINCIPLE
ON--ON DOING THIS.
ON PRETTY MUCH
EVERYTHING, YEAH.
THROW IT ON?
THROW IT ON.
A LITTLE SEASONING SALT.
WELL, THIS THING'S GOT
TO BE UP IN THE SIXES.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S--
VERY HOT.
YOU MARK IT
A LITTLE BIT.
MM-HMM.
I'M GONNA FLIP IT THERE.
I JUST LIKE TO PUT
A LITTLE BUTTER ON IT...
OHH.
LET HER SIT THERE
A LITTLE BIT.
SEASONED SALT,
BUTTER ON MEAT, GRILLED.
UM...
HOW DO YOU WANT
YOUR STEAK?
ON A PLATE.
OH, MEDIUM-RARE.
AS YOU KNOW THE RULE, YOU DON'T
PULL IT RIGHT OFF THE GRILL
AND CUT RIGHT INTO IT.
LET'S JUST WATCH IT.
YOU GOT
TO LET IT SIT.
UH-HUH.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT'S JUST--
THAT'S JUST GREAT.
OHH.
IT'S GOOD.
IT IS GOOD STEAK.
THAT IS GREAT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BUT IT AIN'T JUST KILLER STEAKS
THAT GET HAND-CUT HERE.
SOUVLAKI.
OH, IT'S EXCELLENT.
MAMA'S CLASSIC GREEK RECIPE
WITH A FAMILY TWIST.
(Guy) AND IS IT TRADITIONALLY
MADE WITH PORK TENDERLOIN?
IN GREECE, NO.
HERE, WE--WE DO IT SOFTER,
AND IT'S A LOT
BETTER-TASTING MEAT.
AND ONE TENDERLOIN
MAKES HOW MANY?
TWO OR SO,
PROBABLY.
THEY'RE 12 TO 14 OUNCES,
WHAT WE SERVE.
YOU SERVE
A 14-OUNCE PORTION?
YEAH.
PUT YOUR MEAT IN THERE, A LITTLE
BIT OF SALT, LEMON JUICE--
THAT HELPS--THAT ACID HELPS
BREAK IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
YES.
PEPPER.
AND PUT
SOME WHITE WINE.
AND GARLIC SALT, VINEGAR
AND, OF COURSE, OREGANO.
JUST MIX IT UP, PUT IT
UNDER WRAP FOR FIVE, SIX DAYS.
SO THAT IS WHAT
THIS LOOKS LIKE
AFTER IT MARINATES
FOR A WEEK.
ABOUT A WEEK.
WE'LL PUT IT ON
RIGHT HERE.
(Guy) HOW LONG DOES THIS
TAKE TO COOK?
15 MINUTES OR SO.
AS SHE'S DONE,
WE'LL FINISH IT OFF.
AND WHAT'S
IN THIS MIX?
OH, ABOUT
OLIVE OIL...
OKAY.
OREGANO, SALT, PEPPER,
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
I HEAR THE NATIONAL ANTHEM AT
FLAVOR TOWN GOING OFF RIGHT NOW.
MMM. WOW.
THE FLAVOR IN THAT
IS SO DEEP
AND SO RICH--
THIS IS MONSTER FLAVOR.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE HAD
PORK TASTE THAT FLAVOR. WOW.
THIS IS LIKE
MONSTER TRUCK PORK.
MMM.
I'M GLAD
YOU LIKE IT.
I'M GLAD I DO LIKE IT, TOO.
I'M MOVING IN.
JUST HAS THAT GREAT,
MARINATED, REAL SPICY
TENDER--IT'S GREAT.
AND MAMA'S GREEK RECIPES
JUST KEEP ON COMING--
A GREEK SALAD WITH FETA
AND STUFFED GRAPE LEAVES,
FRESH-MADE BAKLAVA,
EVEN AN ITALIAN CLASSIC
GETS MAMA'S GREEK TWIST.
THERE'S SOMETHING
IN HERE--
I CAN'T FIGURE OUT WHAT IT IS,
BUT IT'S YUMMY.
GREEK MINT.
REALLY. SERIOUSLY.
OKAY, WELL,
I'VE MADE SOME MEATBALLS.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE MADE 'EM
WITH ANY GREEK MINT.
A LITTLE MORE SAUCE.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT. WOW.
MMM. ALL THAT
GREEK MINT IN THERE--
THIS IS
A MONEY MEATBALL.
ALL RIGHT. IT WAS GREAT
MEETING YOU GUYS.
THEY'RE CALLED
MAMA'S MONEY MEATBALLS. YEAH.
THEY'RE VERY,
VERY GOOD.
I COINED
THE PHRASE.
YEAH.
IT'S BIG. IT'LL BE
ALL OVER THE NEWSPAPER.
(woman) WOW.
RIGHT NEXT TO MAMA'S MONEY...
GREEK CHICKEN.
IT'S DELICIOUS. I LOVE IT.
NOW DID YOU EAT THIS AT HOME
WHEN YOU WERE A KID?
YOU BET.
GREEK STYLE IS THIS WAY--
WHATEVER MAMA HAS IN THE OVEN,
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE EATING,
NO MATTER WHAT IT IS.
LITTLE GARLIC, OREGANO,
SALT AND PEPPER...
OKAY.
WE FLIP IT OVER, DO THE SAME.
HEY, YOU'RE DOING PRETTY GOOD.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT'S--YEAH.
YOU DONE
THIS BEFORE?
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
THERE WE GO.
A LITTLE DRIZZLE
ON TOP.
THEN WE JUST PUT--PUT A LITTLE
BIT OF BUTTER INSIDE THERE.
FILL IT ABOUT,
I DON'T KNOW, 1/4 INCH--
SO IT'S GONNA--
YOU HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
AND A LITTLE FAT IN THERE.
YOU SHOULD PUT SOME IN FOR YOU,
TOO. IS OUR BIRD DONE?
WELL, LET'S
TAKE A LOOK.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S PRETTY AWESOME.
NICE AND CRISPY ON TOP.
SMELL ALL THAT.
THAT'S MONEY.
THERE WE GO.
WOW, LOOK
AT HOW JUICY THAT IS.
DUNK IT IN THE--
LOOK AT ALL
THE JUICES.
GET IT
IN THE JUICES.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
THERE YOU GO.
YEAH, YOU'VE LEARNED
TO EAT GREEK WAY, SEE?
YOU ENJOYING THAT?
YEAH. COULD YOU TELL?
VERY GOOD.
I HAVEN'T TALKED MUCH
OR TAKEN A BREATH.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
OHH. FANTA--
I MEAN, KILLER.
OHH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S ABOUT AS BASIC
AS YOU CAN MAKE IT,
AND THAT'S ABOUT AS TENDER
AND JUICY AS YOU CAN GET IT.
THE FOOD NEVER CHANGES.
IT'S ALWAYS REALLY GOOD.
JUST YOUR AVERAGE
OFF-THE-HOOK STEAKHOUSE...
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S A VERY GOOD STEAK.
WITH HOMEMADE GREEK...
IT'S EASY TO BE THE HERO
WHEN YOU GOT YOUR MOM HERE.
THANKS, MOM.
BEHIND THE LIQUOR STORE.
(Guy) DID YOU EXPECT
TO FIND GREEK FOOD
IN THE BACK
OF A LIQUOR STORE?
NO.
WHEN YOU GET INSIDE, YOU'LL BE
VERY SURPRISED WITH THE FOOD.
AND YOU ALWAYS RUN INTO PEOPLE
YOU KNOW OVER HERE.
IS THIS
THE FAMILY TABLE?
(woman) THIS IS
THE FAMILY TABLE.
SO IF I COME IN HERE AND I SEE
SOMEBODY SITTING HERE AT THIS,
I CAN ASSUME THAT IN SOME WAY
OR ANOTHER, THEY'RE FAMILY?
OR THEY'RE
IN TROUBLE.
PRETTY MUCH.
OR THEY'RE
IN TROUBLE.
MAMA, IS IT GONNA BE
POSSIBLE EVERY DAY
FOR YOU TO MAIL FOOD
TO ME, TO CALIFORNIA?
YEAH, SURE.
TRY.
(Lou) SHE WOULD, TOO.
I KNOW SHE WOULD.
UP NEXT...
WHO HAD
THE LAMB SHANK?
WE'RE HEADING
TO A LOUISIANA BAR...
ENJOY.
TO MEET A CHEF...
A LITTLE DASH
OF SALT AND PEPPER.
WHO DOES WHAT HE WANTS.
VERY GOOD
TURTLE SOUP.
WHEN YOU'RE CRUISING DOWN
RIVER ROAD
IN JEFFERSON, LOUISIANA,
DON'T EXPECT TO RUN INTO MUCH.
NOW THERE'S A LOT OF SWAMPLAND,
THE MISSISSIPPI'S
RIGHT OVER THERE,
AND THEN YOU FIND THIS PLACE,
THE RIVERSHACK TAVERN,
AND BOY, ARE YOU
IN FOR A SURPRISE.
TURTLE SOUP?
VERY GOOD TURTLE SOUP.
ONE OF OUR LOCAL CREATURES.
RABBIT.
(man) RABBITS
WITH SPAETZLE.
VERY GOOD.
IT'S A VERY UNIQUE TASTE.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF THINGS YOU
WOULDN'T EXPECT TO GET AT A BAR.
ESPECIALLY ONE...
HERE YOU GO.
THAT LOOKS LIKE THIS.
IT'S JUST BEEN HERE FOREVER.
IT'S JUST LIKE A LANDMARK.
THE BUILDING'S PROBABLY
RIGHT AT 100 YEARS OLD.
AND IT'S BEEN EVERYTHING
FROM A GROCERY STORE TO--
RESTAURANT, A BAR.
HELLO, HOW ARE Y'ALL
DOING TODAY?
WHEN DONNIE THOMAS BOUGHT
THE PLACE A FEW YEARS AGO,
IT CAME WITH A FUNKY DECOR...
YOU'VE GOT THE BIKER,
THE PIRATE...
ARR!
MM-HMM.
(both) THE GOLFER.
A LOYAL LOCAL CROWD...
THIS IS THE FIRST BAR
ON THE WAY HOME FROM WORK.
ORDER UP.
AND A CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF,
MIKE BASKIND...
SHRIMP PO-BOY.
DOING ALL THE BASICS...
I DO THE BURGERS,
THE PO-BOYS.
BUT KNOCKING 'EM DEAD
WITH SERIOUS SPECIALS.
PHONE STARTS RINGING ABOUT 8:00,
WONDERING WHAT THE SPECIAL IS.
WHATEVER I FEEL LIKE DOING THAT
DAY, THAT BECOMES OUR SPECIAL.
WHO HAD
THE WHASKILY WABBIT?
I'VE TURNED PEOPLE ONTO RABBIT
WHO NORMALLY WOULD NEVER TRY IT.
AND THIS IS THE PART
OF THE LEG AND THE THIGH.
GENEROUS AMOUNTS
OF SALT AND PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR--
JUST WANT A NICE BROWN ON THOSE.
BACON FAT.
THAT'S MY PHILOSOPHY.
NEVER GET ENOUGH
BACON FAT, HUH?
GET A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR
ON 'EM, NOT TOO MUCH.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS NEEDS?
I THINK YOU'LL AGREE WITH ME.
YOU KNOW, YOU JUST DON'T
EVER GET ENOUGH BACON FAT.
I KNOW.
THANK YOU.
LET'S TURN 'EM OVER.
AGAIN, WE DON'T REALLY WANT
A WHOLE LOT OF COLOR ON THESE.
WE HAVE OUR MIREPOIX WITH
THE ONIONS, CELERY AND CARROTS.
GARLIC DOWN NOW, TOO?
EH, WHY NOT?
JUST BASICALLY IT'S
TO SWEAT 'EM A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS
MY SACHET D'EPICE.
IT'S BAY LEAVES, THYME
WRAPPED IN A CHEESECLOTH.
LOTS OF WHITE WINE.
(whistles)
NOW LET'S GET
THIS ROLLING.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO?
I'M TALKING ABOUT
LIKE AN HOUR OR SO.
HE'LL SERVE IT
WITH A GREEN ONION
AND CREOLE MUSTARD SPAETZLE.
AND I GOT TO FORCE IT
THROUGH THE HOLES VERY QUICKLY.
AS IT DROPS,
IT COOKS.
KIND OF HIS VERSION OF
GERMAN SAUTEED NOODLE NUGGETS.
A LITTLE DASH
OF SALT AND PEPPER.
OHH, THERE'S
A LITTLE CRUNCH.
READY TO GET OUR RABBIT OUT?
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU CAN SEE THESE ARE BASICALLY
JUST FALLING OF THE BONE.
A NICE
WHITE WINE GRAVY.
BUT NOW--
(imitating Elmer Fudd)
BE VEWY, VEWY QUIET.
I'M TWYING WABBIT.
(normal voice)
THAT IS OUTSTANDING.
NICE AND JUICY,
GREAT FLAVOR.
IT GOT A BIT OF A CRUST
PUT ON THE OUTSIDE,
AND ON THE INSIDE,
IT IS JUST TENDER AND JUICY.
AND THEN THE...
WE DID
THE RIGHT THING.
GREEN ONION SPAETZLE
IS JUST DYNAMITE.
(man) IT DOESN'T HAVE
A WILD TASTE TO IT
LIKE MOST PEOPLE,
I GUESS, WOULD THINK.
THE FLAVOR IS VERY GOOD.
I'D HAD RABBIT,
BUT I'VE NEVER HAD SPAETZLE.
MIKE'S GOOD
ON THE SPECIALS HERE.
SOMETHING DIFFERENT YOU DON'T
FIND IN THE AVERAGE BAR...
WE'RE GONNA
BRAISE THESE?
LIKE BRAISED LAMB SHANKS
WITH GARLIC,
RED WINE AND BAY LEAVES.
WOW, THOSE REALLY
SOAK UP THE RED WINE.
MMM. I KEEP EATING IT.
VERY TENDER. FALLS RIGHT OFF
THE BONE. IT'S VERY GOOD.
(man) IT'S NOT
VERY COMMON.
AND IN A PLACE
LIKE THIS,
I WOULD NEVER
EXPECT TO FIND IT.
NO, NO, NOT IN
A PLACE LIKE THIS.
HOW ABOUT THE
PEANUT-CRUSTED SOFT SHELL CRAB,
SEARED AHI, ALLIGATOR SAUSAGE
OR...
HERE'S
YOUR TURTLE SOUP.
LIKE, TURTLE TURTLE?
YEAH.
SNAPPING TURTLE.
CAN YOU GO CATCH
YOUR OWN TURTLE?
I COULD'VE
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER.
THAT IS THE TURTLE MEAT.
BACON FAT, ALL RIGHT.
THE HOLY TRINITY.
TURTLE MEAT,
GROUND BEEF.
WE'RE GONNA PUT BAY LEAVES,
SACHET D'EPICE IN AGAIN.
IT ADDS A BAY LEAF FLAVOR,
WHICH I REALLY LOVE,
AND I DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT PICKING THE LEAVES OUT.
SOME DICED TOMATOES, GRATED
LEMON ZEST--THE ZEST AND JUICE--
HARD-BOILED EGG,
CHOPPED SPINACH,
SOME SHERRY.
SERIOUSLY?
THE WHOLE BOTTLE?
EH, WELL, WHY NOT?
IT LOOKS LIKE THE TACO SALAD
BEAT UP THE COBB SALAD
AND THE TURTLE JUMPED
IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
THIS IS A LITTLE BIT
OF DARK ROUX.
THIS IS GONNA SIMMER
FOR QUITE A WHILE,
PROBABLY ABOUT
THREE HOURS OR SO.
THREE HOURS, REALLY?
CALF FRIES...
YES.
CHICKEN GIZZARDS...
MM-HMM.
ESCARGOT...
YES.
FREAKY OCTOPUS.
TODAY, WE BRANCH OUT.
I GO AQUAMAN.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TURTLE SOUP.
SOME SHERRY,
FRESHLY CUT GREEN ONIONS.
IT'S TURTLE TIME.
THAT'S A GOOD SIZE.
THAT'S A NICE ONE, TOO.
A TOAST TO TURTLE.
IT'S A REALLY NICE STEW.
THE TEXTURE IS FANTASTIC.
REALLY GOOD FLAVOR.
IT'S GREAT.
BUT YOU GET A REALLY--
A REALLY GOOD BROTH
THAT GOES ALONG
WITH IT.
I DON'T THINK
YOU WOULD BE ABLE
TO TELL SOMEBODY
THAT THIS IS TURTLE
AND NOT
SOME TYPE OF--
SOME TYPE OF ROAST
OR SOME TYPE OF BEEF.
I LIKE IT.
FRESH GREEN ONION--
MMM.
MM-HMM.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT'S A NEW ONE
ON THE LIST.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD TURTLE SOUP.
JUST VERY GOOD TURTLE SOUP.
HE MAKES THE BEST SOUP,
ANYTIME, ALL THE TIME.
THEIR FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
I ALWAYS LOVE THE FOOD HERE
AND THE ATMOSPHERE.
JESSICA, ORDER UP.
AND PEOPLE KNOW
TO COME DOWN HERE
AND TRY DIFFERENT
TYPE FOODS?
THAT'S THE REASON
WE COME TO NEW ORLEANS.
BUT SO IS THIS.
(woman)
AND THE RED BEANS AND RICE.
EVERYONE EATS
RED BEANS AND RICE ON MONDAYS.
UP NEXT, MIKE'S TAKE
ON THIS NEW ORLEANS CLASSIC.
BETTER THAN MY MOM'S.
NO, DON'T SAY THAT.
WE'RE BOTH GONNA GET
KICKED OUT OF THE STATE.
THE RIVERSHACK TAVERN
JUST OUTSIDE OF NEW ORLEANS...
HOW ARE Y'ALL
DOING TODAY?
IS A ROADSIDE BAR
(man) MARGARITA.
(woman) RAZZY-RITA.
WITH A SERIOUS RESTAURANT KICK.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF COLOR ON 'EM.
WHERE CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF
MIKE BASKIND
IS CRANKING OUT
ALL KINDS OF SPECIALS...
WHO HAD
THE WHASKILY WABBIT?
LIKE RABBIT
WITH GREEN ONION SPAETZLE
AND SNAPPIN' TURTLE SOUP.
GOOD TURTLE SOUP.
IT'S WHAT YOU WOULD EXPECT
TO SEE IN NEW ORLEANS.
BUT SOMETIMES
THIS LOUISIANA CROWD
JUST WANTS A LOCAL FAVORITE.
MONDAYS IS
RED BEANS AND RICE DAY.
GOOD RED BEANS AND RICE
IS CREAMY.
THIS HAS ENOUGH HEAT
TO GIVE IT A GOOD FLAVOR.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
MAKE RED BEANS AND RICE,
WHICH DOESN'T MEAN
JUST RED BEANS AND RICE.
THERE'S A LOT MORE INVOLVED,
AND OUR OLD FRIEND BACON FAT.
SO KIDNEY BEANS
ARE DRIED.
RIGHT, AND THEY'VE BEEN SOAKED
OVERNIGHT IN JUST WATER.
WOULD YOU LOOK
AT THIS BIG OL'--
HOLY HOCK.
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS PUT OUR HAM HOCK IN.
A LITTLE BIT OF WORCESTERSHIRE,
A LITTLE BIT OF HOT SAUCE.
OUR OLD FRIEND THE TRINITY--
VEGETABLES, BAY LEAVES.
TURN AROUND JUMPER.
HUH?
SO THIS IS GONNA GO IN
A SIMMER FOR FOUR HOURS?
ABOUT FOUR HOURS OR SO, AND IT'S
GONNA GET NICE AND BREAK DOWN,
AND GET NICE
AND CREAMY.
AND THE HOCK
IS DISINTEGRATED?
THEY ACTUALLY--
YOU MIGHT FIND SOME--
THERE'S A CHUNK IN THERE.
WELL, THERE'S A CHUNK.
THE BACON FAT MAKES THIS
A LOT CREAMIER, TOO.
WHAT IS THIS?
YOU DO THIS WITH A GRILLED
CHICKEN OR A SMOKED SAUSAGE.
IT'S KIND OF SWEET,
HAS A MAPLE SORT OF GLAZE.
IT COMPLEMENTS THINGS
REALLY WELL, I THINK.
I'M DREDGING FOR CHUNK.
THAT'S TOO GOOD
TO BE GOOD FOR YOU.
I GET A WHANG
TO IT.
LIKE, I'M GETTING A LOT OF
THE WORCESTERSHIRE OR SOMETHING.
IT JUST HAS A DEPTH FAR BEYOND
JUST REGULAR BEANS AND RICE.
I TELL YOU, THIS HAS
THAT SAME CREAMY, VELVETY,
I-WANT-MORE,
YOU KNOW,
GOING ON WITH IT.
IT'S JUST DYNAMITE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MMM. TAKE IT AWAY.
I--LIKE, SERIOUSLY.
I'LL BE RIGHT OVER HERE
ASLEEP.
OKAY.
AFTER I HAVE
ONE MORE BITE.
(woman) THE FLAVOR
FROM THE SAUSAGE KIND OF
COMBINES WITH
THE BEANS AND RICE NICELY.
REALLY CREAMY, AND IT HAS
A REALLY GOOD FLAVOR TO IT.
JUST LIKE EVERYTHING
MIKE'S COOKING UP.
SHELLY,
SHRIMP PO-BOY.
THEIR FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
ONCE THEY COME HERE,
THEY KEEP COMING BACK HERE.
IT'S JUST
A GOOD LOCAL PLACE.
(woman) HERE YOU GO.
IT'S A ONE-OF-A-KIND, YOU KNOW.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND ANOTHER.
IT'S THE SHACK.
SO--LEGIT?
LEGIT.
BIG TIME.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
GREAT JOB, CHEF.
SERIOUSLY.
DON'T YOU LOVE IT?
REALLY DYNAMITE.
PLEASURE.
I'LL TAKE THIS TO GO.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINER, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HEY, HAVE YOU EVER TAKEN
A CULINARY CLASS AT ALL?
NOPE. NO, SIR.
WHERE DO YOU LEARN THE TERM
"RENDERING DOWN THE FAT"?
UH...
FOOD NETWORK.