HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
ON A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IT'S THE MEMPHIS
BARBECUE TOUR.
GIVE ME A JUMBO
PORK COMBO.
HE'S HUNGRY, BABY.
(Guy) WE'RE TAKING YOU
WHERE THE LOCALS WOULD...
THIS IS REALLY
TENNESSEE BARBECUE.
FOR A CHOPPED PORK SANDWICH
THE WAY MR. LEONARD FIRST MADE
'EM MORE THAN 85 YEARS AGO.
YOU JUST POUR
IT ON LIKE THAT?
TILL IT SIZZLES
ON THE GRILL.
THAT'S DELICIOUS, MAN.
A LITTLE JOINT WHERE
THEY'RE DOING THE CLASSICS,
AND SOMETHIN' ELSE.
I HAVEN'T SEEN A LOT
OF CORNISH HENS ON MENUS.
THAT'S THE UNIQUE THING.
MM. THAT'S TENDER.
THE PLACE NEAR GRACELAND
THAT'LL BRING YOU BY LIMO
FOR A TASTE OF THEIR RIBS.
NICE AND TENDER.
TENDER AS A WOMAN'S HEART.
AND SPEED BARBECUE
LIKE YOU'VE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
WE'VE GOT A JUMBO COMBO.
21!
LET IT FLY, BABY.
WITH SLAW.
FEEL LIKE A STOCK BROKER.
I'M ON THE FLOOR.
DOWN--STOCK--UP!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
THE MEMPHIS BARBECUE TOUR ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO WE'RE STARTING OUR TOUR
WITH A NAME THAT'S BEEN BIG
IN MEMPHIS BARBECUE
FOR MORE THAN 85 YEARS.
NOW THERE REALLY WAS A LEONARD,
AND THEY'RE DOING
EVERYTHING HERE THE WAY
HE WAS DOING IT BACK IN 1922.
YOU GOT OUR RIB ENDS.
OH, IT'S THE BEST
BARBECUE IN MEMPHIS.
THIS DINNER HAS BEAN, SLAW
AND HUSH PUPPIES.
THE MEAT THAT THEY USE
IS REALLY GOOD.
YOU KNOW, THE RIBS ARE--
ALWAYS GOT A LOT OF MEAT ON 'EM.
A REGULAR MR. LEONARD
WITH ONION RINGS.
BARBECUE CAPITAL
OF THE WORLD,
SO, YEAH, I THINK
IT IS A MEMPHIS THING.
(Guy) HOW DOES THIS STACK UP
IN THE WORLD OF BARBECUE?
IT'S THE BEST,
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED.
KIND OF LIKE THE GRANDFATHER
OF ALL THE BARBECUE PLACES
IN THE CITY.
NEVER CHANGES HERE.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
CAUSE THEY'RE STILL USING
THE ORIGINAL RECIPES...
MMM.
FROM THE '20s AND '30s...
LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN LEONARD HEUBERGER FIRST
STARTED MAKING IT ALL HIS WAY.
SINCE 1962,
I'VE BEEN MAKING IT.
SINCE 1962?
YEAH.
DAN BROWN STARTED AT LEONARD'S
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
IT'S THE ONLY THING
I'VE EVER DONE.
WHEN HE CAME BACK
FROM MILITARY SERVICE,
DAN CAME BACK TO LEONARD'S.
JUST GET THESE OFF.
23 YEARS LATER,
HE FINALLY BOUGHT THE PLACE.
THIS IS WHAT
I WANTED TO DO,
AND IT CERTAINLY
WORKED OUT GOOD FOR ME.
YOU STAY WITH SOMETHING
THAT'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY DEPENDABLE, AND PEOPLE
COME BECAUSE IT'S GOOD.
ALL ACROSS THE MENU.
THE SLOW-COOKED RIBS
IS WHAT I LIKE.
BARBECUE CHICKEN'S
JUST DELICIOUS.
AND THE BIG HITTER HERE
IS A CHOPPED PORK SANDWICH
NAMED FOR MR. LEONARD
HIMSELF.
BIG LEONARD TO GO?
MM-HMM.
PULLED AND CHOPPED
AND SMOKED JUST RIGHT.
AND FLAVORED WITH--GET THIS--
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
SEASONING? DRY RUB?
NO. HICKORY SMOKE.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR ABOUT 180 TO 190 DEGREES
AFTER TEN HOURS.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'LL GET 'EM ALL, AND WE'LL
PUT 'EM ALL IN THE CHARCOAL.
WE'LL KEEP
COOKIN' 'EM?
BROWN 'EM.
GET 'EM GOOD AND CRUNCHY
ON THE OUTSIDE.
SO HICKORY OVER HERE,
BUT CHARCOAL ON THAT--CHARCOAL?
YEAH.
SWING IT
ALL THE WAY BACK.
JUST GONNA HAVE
TO CHUCK 'EM IN THERE?
I'M JUST GONNA SET 'EM.
THOSE ARE BEAUTIFUL.
NO MOP, NO NOTHIN'?
NOTHING, NOTHING.
LOOK AT THAT CRUST.
LOOK AT THAT BREAKING OFF.
YEAH.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THERE'S
NO SALT AND PEPPER IN THAT.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA GO PEEL SOME
OF THIS OFF, MAKE A SANDWICH?
YEAH.
I JUST REACH IN AND GET SOME OF
THE WHITE, SOME OF THE BROWN...
ALL RIGHT.
AND THEN CHOP IT?
NO, NOT LIKE THAT.
YOU--
YOU GOTTA GET THROUGH THAT.
IF YOU DON'T--
I WAS GONNA GET THROUGH IT.
I DON'T WANT IT
FLUFFY ON THERE, THOUGH.
I WANT THE MEAT KINDA
COMPRESSED.
CONDENSED.
YEAH.
LIKE THAT? IS THAT GOOD?
YEAH, YEAH.
AND JUST POUR IT ON
LIKE THAT?
UNTIL IT RUNS DOWN ON THE GRILL
AND SIZZLES ON THE GRILL.
NOW WHAT?
A BIG SCOOP OF SLAW.
OVERFLOWIN' LIKE A DOUBLE.
LIKE THAT?
YEAH, MM-HMM.
RIGHT ON TOP--
ON TOP?
RIGHT ON TOP. DON'T SPREAD
IT OUR OR NOTHIN'.
OKAY.
IT'S HOT.
THAT'S DELICIOUS, MAN,
NICE AND TENDER,
AND, YOU KNOW, I REALLY LIKE
THE CHOP OF THE MEAT.
YOU REALLY GET THE PORK FLAVOR
JUST OF THE MEAT ITSELF...
YEAH.
AND THEN YOU GET
REALLY NICE
RICH FLAVOR
OUT OF THAT SAUCE.
THAT'S ALL-STAR BARBECUE
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
YOU'RE THE MAN.
THEY GIVE YOU LOTS
AND LOTS OF MEAT.
IN FACT, IT'S REALLY TOO BIG TO
PICK UP WITH YOUR HANDS AND EAT,
AND THEY PUT THE SLAW ON IT
AND THE SWEET SAUCE,
AND IT'S JUST
ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
AND THEY'RE SAUCE IS PROBABLY
THE BEST YOU'LL EVER EAT.
MR. LEONARD'S
ORIGINAL RECIPE...
TASTES REALLY GOOD.
SO POPULAR, THEY DO IT THESE
DAYS 32 GALLONS AT A TIME.
WE START WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER?
YEP.
WANNA PUT THE VINEGAR IN.
LOOK AT THE LITTLE GUY
FROM CALIFORNIA
FILLING UP
THE VINEGAR VAT.
I'VE HEARD OF SOME VINEGAR-BASED
SAUCE DOWN IN THE CAROLINAS.
THIS IS BANANAS.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
YEAH.
LEMON JUICE.
MUSTARD. UH-OH, UH-OH.
WE'LL MIX THAT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I COULD POLE-VAULT OVER
THE CASTLE WALL WITH THIS.
SUGAR, PAPRIKA, CHILI POWDER,
AND THEN ALL SORTS
OF LITTLE SPICES.
YEAH, THERE'S A LOT
OF SUGAR IN THAT.
HOW MANY POUNDS IS THIS?
RIGHT AT 75.
YOU KNOW THIS IS
GONNA SPLATTER.
I'M GONNA BE OVER HERE.
THAT'S IT.
THEN WE JUST
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
WOW, THAT TURNED A NICE, DARK,
DEEP, RICH COLOR REAL QUICK.
THICKENING UP,
TOO, ISN'T IT?
YEAH, IT IS.
THE FLAVOR'S SWEET,
KIND OF LIKE,
YOU KNOW, THAT SOUTHERN TASTE.
ON THE CHOPPED PORK SANDWICH,
THE RIBS, PORK DINNER,
WITH SIDES LIKE BEANS,
HOMEMADE SLAW...
IN MEMPHIS, YOU HAVE TO HAVE
SLAW WITH YOUR BARBECUE.
NOODLES ARE
READY TO GO.
EVEN PASTA.
YOU GOT A RAVIOLI
AND RIBS.
TWO OF MY FAVORITE
THINGS IN LIFE.
SKETTI AND RIBS.
I'LL TELL YOU, BARBECUE MAN,
THAT'S SOME GOOD SPAGHETTI.
YEAH, YEAH.
MMM. NICE BOLOGNESE SAUCE.
GOOD JOB.
THIS IS A MEMPHIS BARBECUE
TRADITION HERE.
THE WHOLE PLACE IS...
WE DROVE 86 MILES THIS MORNING
JUST TO HAVE BARBECUE.
WE DROVE ALL THE WAY
FROM MISSISSIPPI
TO COME TO TENNESSEE
TO EAT A BARBECUE.
WE HAVE A COUPLE OF BARBECUE
PLACES IN NASHVILLE,
BUT I DON'T EAT THERE.
AS LONG AS THE NAME LEONARD'S
IS ON THE RESTAURANT,
I FEEL LIKE THAT'S
WHAT I GOTTA DO.
THEY HAVE TO BE ABLE TO KNOW
THAT WHEN THEY COME HERE,
IT'S GONNA BE
WHAT THEY HAD LAST WEEK,
LAST YEAR, LAST DECADE,
LAST CENTURY.
DO YOU HAVE A GARDEN HOSE--
SOMEWHERE I CAN CLEAN UP
A LITTLE BIT?
THERE YOU GO.
MY GOSH. CONGRATS, MAN.
NO WONDER 85 YEARS HAVE BEEN
GOIN' ON. THAT IS ON POINT.
UP NEXT...
WE'VE GOT A JUMBO COMBO,
MILD SAUCE.
21!
GIVE ME A WING
SNACK, BABY.
CHECK OUT THE LUNCH LINE
AT THIS PLACE...
THIS IS EFFICIENT
RIGHT HERE.
REGULAR, NO SLAW.
NUMBER TWO!
BOOM, BOOM, BOOM.
WHERE THEY'RE PILING IN
FOR A ONE-OF-A-KIND TAKE
ON RIB TIPS.
ST. LOUIS-STYLE
BUTTON BONE RIB TIPS.
WOW. I'LL HAVE
TO WRITE THAT DOWN.
WE'RE STILL ROLLING ON OUR
MEMPHIS BARBECUE TOUR.
NOW WE'RE HEADED
TO A PLACE CALLED TOM'S.
A LOT OF FOLKS TOLD US WE HAD
TO COME CHECK OUT THE RIB TIPS,
AND ESPECIALLY THE FLOOR SHOW.
WE GOT A JUMBO COMBO.
MAKE IT WET.
TAKE A NUMBER. 15, SIR.
21!
LET IT FLY, BABY.
HERE, IT'S GONNA FLY.
THE DUDE WITH THE KNIFE...
HE HASN'T LOST
A FINGER YET.
NUMBER 41,
BUFFALO PLATE.
I GOT A PORK CHOP COMBO
WITH SLAW.
MAKE IT HOT JUST LIKE
THIS LADY, PLEASE.
I FEEL LIKE A STOCK BROKER.
I'M ON THE FLOOR.
DOWN--STOCK--UP!
YOU COME IN,
YOU PLACE YOUR ORDER...
THEN YOU PICK THE RIGHT BAG.
PERSONAL COMPUTER FOR $3.29.
OH, THAT'S PORK CHOP?
YOU YELL IT?
JUMBO BEEF,
PLEASE, ANNA.
THEY MOVE SO QUICK.
YOU GET YOUR FOOD
IN A MATTER OF MINUTES.
IN AND OUT.
AND IT'S GREAT.
SPEED BARBECUE
WITH ALL THE CLASSICS...
IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
FROM BRISKET AND RIBS
TO CHOPPED PORK, CHICKEN,
TURKEY AND PORK CHOPS
WITH--GET THIS--
A MEDITERRANEAN KICK.
HERB RUB ON THAT IS--
IS CRAZY.
THAT'S A GREEK-STYLE RUB.
ORIGINAL OWNER--
HE WAS FROM GREECE.
WE KEPT THE SAME RECIPE.
IF IT'S NOT BROKE,
YOU DON'T FIX IT.
LIGHT SAUCE, PLEASE.
ADAM ITAYEM BOUGHT THIS PLACE
FROM A DUDE NAMED, YEAH, TOM,
13 YEARS AGO.
DID YOU KNOW
ABOUT THIS PLACE?
I NEVER KNEW
THIS EXISTED.
IT WAS JUST AN OLD RUSTIC
BUILDING--SOMETHING THAT LOOKED
LIKE A SHACK. THEY HAD PEOPLE
STANDING OUT THE DOOR.
WHICH MEANT EATING HERE
TOOK TIME.
YOU HAD TO, YOU KNOW,
JUST SIT AND WAIT, BUT NOW...
CAN I HELP YOU, SIR?
SMALL BARBECUE.
GIVE ME A JUMBO COMBO.
I'LL HAVE
THE JUMBO PORK.
GIVE ME A BARBECUE
CHICKEN...
THIS IS EFFICIENT, THEN.
BOOM, BOOM, BOOM.
IT'S GOTTA BE THIS FAST.
THIS IS AN INDUSTRIAL
PARK AREA.
AND LUNCH
IS ON THE TIME CARD.
MOST PEOPLE HAVE 30 MINUTES. YOU
OUTTA HERE IN ABOUT 10 OR 15.
NUMBER FIVE!
I CAN'T ASK
FOR NOTHIN' BETTER.
IT'S TOP OF THE LINE.
REAL GOOD BARBECUE.
DONE TOM'S WAY.
THAT'S RIB TIPS.
THEIR RIB TIPS
ARE DIFFERENT.
WOW.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT CUT IT IS.
IT'S A CUT FROM THE LOIN.
ST. LOUIS-STYLE
BUTTON BONE RIB TIPS.
I'LL HAVE TO
WRITE THAT DOWN.
SO THIS IS THE LOIN
AND THIS IS THE RIB.
WHERE IS THIS TIP
COMING FROM?
IT'S SHAVED RIGHT
ON THE TOP AT AN ANGLE.
I LIKE IT. YOU GET THESE
SPECIALLY CUT THEN?
IT'S NOT EASY TO GET.
IT'S NOT VERY
EASY TO GET.
YOU GOTTA KNOW SOMEBODY.
SO NOW TO SEASON IT. NOW HOW
DO PEOPLE TAKE TO THIS IDEA
OF DOING--TAKING BARBECUE
AND KIND OF TWEAKING IT
A LITTLE BIT AND THROWING
A GREEK SPIN ON IT?
IT'S BEEN WORKING.
WE START OFF WITH A CUP
OF SEASONING SALT.
OKAY.
REGULAR SALT.
WE NEED PLENTY
OF THYME IN THIS.
LIKE I SAID,
THIS IS A GREEK-STYLE RUB
THAT WE'RE MAKING.
CHILI POWDER,
GROUND OREGANO.
SO WE REALLY DO TAKE IT
INTO THE GREEK FACTOR.
YES, SIR.
WE GOT PICKLING SPICE.
THAT'S PROBABLY SOMETHING
I HAVEN'T SEEN IN RUBS.
IT'S A BIG
MEDITERRANEAN THING.
CELERY SALT.
I LIKE IT.
GOT SOME CELERY SALT.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS, AS WELL
AS A LITTLE SALT FACTOR.
WE GOT SOME PAPRIKA.
WE GOT SOME GARLIC SALT.
WE GOT SOME RED PEPPER,
AND BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
WE GOT SOME NUTMEG
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
OKAY, MIX IT UP,
GOOD TO GO?
GREAT COLORS.
THAT'S MEDITERRANEAN.
WE DON'T LIKE TO USE IT RIGHT
AWAY. WE LIKE TO LET IT SIT.
LET IT SIT AND MARRY
A LITTLE BIT?
YEAH.
MARINATE A LITTLE BIT
TOGETHER.
WE USE IT ON THE BOLOGNA,
THE PORK SHOULDER,
THE BEEF BRISKET.
WE DO IT ON THE CHICKEN...
AND THE SPARE RIBS,
BABY BACKS,
SMOKED TURKEY LEGS
AND THOSE RIB TIPS.
JUST THE DRY SEASONING
ON TOP?
WE WANT TO KEEP IT
A LITTLE MOIST,
SO WE JUST ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
TAKE THE RUB...
OKAY.
JUST ENOUGH TO THROW
A LITTLE FLAVOR ON IT?
EXACTLY.
WE DON'T WANT IT TOO SPICY,
'CAUSE IT'LL DRY IT OUT.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
A LOT OF PEOPLE COME IN HERE,
AND EVEN AFTER WE COOK 'EM,
THEY WANT US TO PUT
THE RUB ON TOP OF IT.
REALLY?
NOW THIS IS GONNA MARINATE
FOR ANOTHER 24 HOURS?
THIS WILL MARINATE
FOR 24 HOURS.
LET'S PUT IT NIGHT-NIGHT.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
OPEN THE PIT UP,
THROW 'EM ON.
YOU KNOW THAT'S
A HOT GRILL.
NOW HOW LONG DOES
IT TAKE TO COOK THESE?
AN HOUR AND A HALF,
TWO HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW IS THERE AN ART
TO DOING THIS?
JUST PICK OUT THE BONE.
MMM. IT'S SUPER TENDER.
IT'S NOT A RIB.
IT'S NOT RIB MEAT.
NO.
IT'S LOIN MEAT WITH RIB.
GREAT SPICE.
YOU CAN TASTE THE PORK.
I'VE HAD A LOT OF BARBECUE,
BUT THIS LITTLE SNACK
RIGHT HERE
MIGHT BE SOME
OF THE BEST BARBECUE.
HOW ARE THE RIB TIPS?
GREAT.
OFF THE HOOK.
OFF THE HOOK,
OFF THE CHAIN.
ALL THE TIME.
YOU GONNA FINISH 'EM ALL?
OF COURSE I'D LIKE ONE.
I CAN SEE WHY YOU'RE
SO POPULAR, ADAM.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
DO YOU SERVE IN A DAY?
WE SERVE EASY 1,500,
2,000 PEOPLE A DAY.
GIVE ME A JUMBO PORK,
PLEASE.
ORDERING SANDWICHES
AND FULL MEALS
WITH A CHOICE
OF 11 MAIN ITEMS,
NINE SIDES
AND TWO KINDS OF FRIES.
SAUCE ON THE SIDE, BABY.
S.O.S.!
THAT'S TRADITIONAL
MEMPHIS STYLE--
BARBECUE DRY
AND SAUCE ON THE SIDE.
YOU DIP INTO THE SAUCE.
YOU LIKE YOUR
BARBECUE DRY?
YEAH, THEN YOU DIP IT.
I LIKE TO GET THE FINGERS
IN THERE, TOO.
ONCE YOU ADD THE SAUCE,
IT GIVES IT ITS OWN SIGNATURE.
AND THAT SIGNATURE STARTS
WITH THE SAME DRY RUB
THEY USE ON THE MEAT.
THIS IS WHAT ACTUALLY
BRINGS OUT EVERYTHING.
YOU CAN SEE THE SPICES--
A UNIQUE FLAVOR
FOR MEMPHIS BASICALLY.
THE SAUCE IS EXCELLENT.
JUST RIGHT.
THE RIGHT MIX.
IT'S JUST SMOOTH.
AND IT'S THE KEY INGREDIENT
IN THEIR VERSION
OF A LOCAL CLASSIC.
BOLOGNA BARBECUE
SANDWICH.
THEY DO IT ALL OUT.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY
TASTE THAT IT'S SEASONED.
SO WE SLICE THIS
HOW THICK?
AS THICK AS THIS
THING WILL GO.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE BIT
OF...
A LITTLE BARBECUE
SAUCE ON IT.
AND THEN HOW LONG
DO WE LET IT MARINATE?
OVERNIGHT.
HUT, HUT, HUT! HIKE!
PROBABLY SOMETHING YOU'VE
NOT SEEN AT HOME BEFORE.
MARINATED THICK-SLICED
DRY-RUBBED BOLOGNA.
TENNESSEE ROUND STEAK.
MY UNCLE LOU TOLD ME THAT.
YOU CAN HEAR IT SIZZLING.
IT'S TALKING TO ME.
MMM. LOOK WHAT JUST POPPED
INTO MY WORLD.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT
RIGHT THERE.
THE COOLNESS OF THE SLAW
WITH THE CRUNCH.
I NEED SIX OF THOSE TO GO.
IT'S MESSY,
BUT IT'S GOOD.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL EXPERIENCE.
THE TASTE,
THE QUALITY,
THE TEXTURE--EVERYTHING
IS JUST WONDERFUL.
CAN I HELP YOU, SIR?
WHEN YOU
BOUGHT THIS PLACE,
DID YOU THINK IT WOULD CONTINUE
TO BLOW UP LIKE THIS?
I DIDN'T...
BABY BACK!
BUT I KNEW I HAD
A GOOD PRODUCT,
WE GOT A JUMBO COMBO.
41, BUFFALO PLATE!
IF YOU CAN COOK IT, THEN IT'S
GONNA HAVE YOUR CHARACTER.
IF YOU PUT YOUR HEART IN IT,
IT'S GONNA SHOW.
YOU DON'T LOOK A DAY OVER 25,
BUT I'M GONNA GIVE YOU 30 TODAY,
IS THAT OKAY?
THANK YOU.
NEXT ON THE MEMPHIS
BARBECUE TOUR...
ORDER--RACK OF RIBS
FOR TWO.
HUGE SLABS OF RIBS...
RIBS ARE THE BEST.
THAT DRY RUB
IS FANTASTIC.
JUST DOWN THE ROAD
FROM GRACELAND.
YOU DON'T SEE A LOT
OF LOCALS AT GRACELAND,
BUT YOU SEE A LOT OF LOCALS
HERE AT MARLOWE'S.
USUALLY ON TRIPLE D, YOU SEE ME
CRUISING THAT SWEET RED CAMARO,
BUT NOT THIS TIME.
IT'S A PINK LIMO, BABY,
BECAUSE THE NEXT STOP
ON OUR MEMPHIS BARBECUE TOUR IS
SUCH A GREAT LOCAL ATTRACTION,
THEY'RE RUNNING
A FLEET OF THESE THINGS.
YOU SEE, FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
A TRIP TO MEMPHIS
MEANS FIRST YOU HIT GRACELAND,
THEN YOU COME HERE TO MARLOWE'S.
I'VE BEEN TO NORTH CAROLINA
AND KANSAS CITY,
BUT I LIKE THE TASTE
OF THIS THE BEST.
I'M FROM MIAMI, FLORIDA.
I'M FROM ATLANTA, GEORGIA.
I'M FROM
CHATTANOOGA, TENNESSEE.
IS IT A TOURIST JOINT,
OR IS IT A LOCAL JOINT?
IT'S BOTH.
I'M A LOCAL.
DON'T SEE A LOT OF
LOCALS AT GRACELAND,
BUT YOU SEE A LOT
OF LOCALS HERE AT MARLOWE'S.
'CAUSE WHOEVER'S EATING IT,
THIS IS MEMPHIS LEGIT.
GREAT MEMPHIS BARBECUE
HAS TO HAVE GOOD SMOKE,
AND IT'S GOTTA HAVE
A GOOD DEPTH TO IT...
GRILL LOW AND SLOW
FOR PRETTY MUCH
HOWEVER LONG IT TAKES.
AND IT'S GOTTA HAVE
A GOOD DRY RUB ON TOP OF IT.
BARBECUING IS A TECHNIQUE,
NOT A SAUCE. THE SAUCE HAS
TO COMPLEMENT THE TECHNIQUE.
BEST BARBECUE
IN THE WORLD.
IS IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
ORDER--RACK
OF RIBS FOR TWO.
THEY'RE DOING IT ALL.
FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
THE RIBS ARE THE BEST.
BARBECUED CHICKEN. ABSOLUTELY
DELICIOUS LIKE I LIKE IT.
GREAT BEEF BRISKET.
BARBECUED PORK DINNER.
IT'S ALWAYS TENDER.
LIKE SOME OTHER MEMPHIS JOINTS,
THEY'RE EVEN PAIRING
BARBECUE WITH SPAGHETTI.
I JUST THOUGHT
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
BUT THIS PLACE HAS AN ITALIAN
HISTORY TO GO WITH IT.
I PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC IN EVERYTHING.
YOU SEE, TONY GIGLIOTTI
FIRST OPENED MARLOWE'S
AS A MOSTLY ITALIAN RESTAURANT,
BUT OVER THE YEARS,
HE TURNED MORE AND MORE
TO WHAT MEMPHIS LOVES MOST.
FULL RACK OF RIBS!
AND NOW HE AND HIS DAUGHTER
MISSY...
HEY, GUYS!
ARE PACKIN' 'EM INTO
WHAT'S BECOME A MEMPHIS
BARBECUE FAVORITE.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
AN INSTITUTION.
IF YOU WANT GOOD BARBECUE,
YOU COME TO MARLOWE'S.
THEY JUST GOT THEIR OWN FLAVOR
AND THEIR OWN TASTE.
IT STARTS WITH THE DRY RUB
MANAGER CHRIS NEILSEN
IS MAKING.
THIS IS SEASONING SALT.
THAT'S SEASONING SALT?
SEASONING SALT. UH, THERE'S
TWO OTHER THINGS IN THERE.
SO SEASON SALT AND TWO THINGS
YOU'RE NOT GONNA TELL ME.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT OF
SUGAR, A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
LITTLE CHILI POWDER.
SOME CHILI POWDER
IN HERE.
GARLIC. LOTS OF GARLIC.
GOT ITALIANS IN HERE.
WE GOTTA USE GARLIC. OF COURSE,
THIS IS OUR CAJUN SEASONING.
OF COURSE.
IT'S GOT WHITE PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER IN IT.
IT'S WHAT YOU USE, YOU KNOW,
CAJUN FOOD KIND OF STUFF.
A LITTLE
CUMIN IN THAT?
A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN.
SEE? YOU'RE RIGHT ON.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME PEPPER IN THERE.
OF COURSE, SOME PAPRIKA
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF ONION POWDER.
GONNA PUT A LID ON HERE.
THEY USE THE RUB
ON EVERYTHING HERE,
BUT THE TOP DOG
AT THIS JOINT IS...
THE RIBS--
THE HALF A RACK OF RIBS,
OR WHOLE RACK
IF I'M REAL HUNGRY.
I ALWAYS GET THE RIBS--
GET THE FULL RACK OF RIBS.
NOT ONLY DO I PUT 'EM ON,
I RUB IT IN,
BECAUSE YOU NEED TO BREAK
THE FABRIC OF THE SKIN
A LITTLE TO GET
THAT FLAVOR ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
WE'RE COOKING IT
FOR 12 HOURS,
AND 12 HOURS--
YOU'RE GONNA COOK A RACK
FOR 12 HOURS?
AT WHAT TEMPERATURE?
225 DEGREES.
IS THERE ANYTHING LEFT
IN 12 HOURS?
YOU WATCH AND SEE.
THIS IS THE OLD HICKORY?
THIS IS THE OLD
HICKORY MACHINE.
NOW WHAT KIND OF WOOD
ARE WE USING?
THE ONLY WOOD TO USE--
FRUITWOOD.
WE USE APPLE WOOD.
SO IT PUTS A LITTLE
MOISTURE ON THERE.
50% APPLE, 50% WATER,
AND IT JUST GIVES IT--
GIVES IT SOME
MOISTURE TO IT,
PLUS IT GIVES IT THAT LITTLE
SWEET APPLE FLAVOR TO IT.
NOW WE'RE NOT GONNA
PUT SAUCE ON 'EM?
NOT NOW. NOT UNTIL
WE TAKE 'EM BACK.
THAT RACK.
YOU GOT IT.
PULLS OFF THE BONE NICELY.
THAT DRY RUB IS FANTASTIC.
NICE AND TENDER.
TENDER AS A WOMAN'S HEART.
I TASTE THE SMOKED SEASONING
FROM THEIR SLOW COOKING,
THE SWEETNESS IN THE SAUCE.
I LIKE IT 'CAUSE
IT WAS ELVIS' FAVORITE.
THAT WAS HIS FAVORITE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE ACTUALLY USE A RECIPE
THAT WE--TO START WITH--
THAT WE GOT FROM
ONE OF ELVIS' COOKS,
AND WE WORKED WITH IT
AND GOT A RECIPE THAT WE LIKE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME TOMATO SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
LEMON JUICE, ORANGE JUICE...
HONEY?
A LITTLE BIT OF HONEY.
SYRUP.
LIKE WAFFLE SYRUP?
YEAH, LIKE WAFFLE SYRUP.
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
NOW SOME MOONSHINE?
A LITTLE BIT OF MOONSHINE.
NO, THIS IS VINEGAR.
PUT SOME MOLASSES IN THERE.
OH.
WE NEED TO ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF KICK TO IT.
NO--HEY, WHOA, WHOA.
NOT TOO MUCH.
NO, I'M JUST OVER HERE.
YEAH. THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
ONE BOX OF BROWN SUGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF CHILI POWDER.
YOU THINK--A LITTLE?
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT.
WE GOTTA ADD A LITTLE FLAVOR,
A LITTLE HOT FLAVOR.
YOU THINK? WHAT IS IT?
UH, THIS IS--
HERE. LET ME JUST TASTE IT.
I JUST WANT TO TASTE IT.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU CAN TASTE IT.
WOW.
THAT'S GOT SOME TANG.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT GO
FOR A GOOD 45 MINUTES,
SIMMER DOWN,
AND IT'S ALL READY TO GO.
JUST GRAB THIS--
THE LITTLE MOP?
THAT'S IT.
THERE YOU GO.
OH. THAT'S NOT
GONNA BE BAD.
MMM.
SAUCE GOOD? EXCELLENT.
NICE TANG, NOT TOO SWEET.
BOY, THAT'S GOT
ENOUGH PUNCH. MMM.
JUST THE SAUCE AND THE SPICES
AND EVERYTHING--I LOVE IT.
OF COURSE, I LOVE TO GET IT
ALL OVER ME, TOO.
IF YOU WANT TO EAT RIBS,
YOU GOTTA HAVE A MESS.
WHAT A NICE EXPERIENCE
OF BARBECUE.
AND SOMETIMES WHEN YOU
COME TO A PLACE LIKE THIS,
YOU THINK, "OH, YOU KNOW,
THEY JUST GET ALL THEIR HYPE
"AND ENERGY OFF THE THEME
AND BEING SO CLOSE TO GRACELAND.
THEY REALLY DON'T HAVE TO DO
THE REAL DEAL ON THE FOOD,"
AND YOU GUYS ARE DOING
A REALLY NICE JOB.
YOU CAN HIT EVERY
PORK PLACE AROUND HERE,
BUT YOU'LL ONLY GET
THIS TASTE HERE.
IT DON'T TASTE LIKE
EVERYBODY ELSE'S BARBECUE.
THE ELVIS FANS THAT COME HERE,
THE LOCALS--THEY COME HERE
BECAUSE MARLOWE'S HAS BEEN
A HOME PLACE FOR ALL 'EM
FOR YEARS.
BACK WHEN I WAS A KID,
I CAME HERE A LONG TIME AGO
WITH MY FATHER.
WHEN I SAW THE GRACELAND SIGN,
I SAID, "MAN I GOTTA
GO BACK TO THAT PLACE."
HAS ANYBODY EVER TOLD YOU
YOU LOOK LIKE
MY FIFTH GRADE SCHOOL TEACHER.
I MEAN, YOU LOOK--
DON'T BE CRUEL, MAN.
UP NEXT...
HOWDY!
A JOINT FAMOUS
FOR SOMETHING YOU JUST
DON'T FIND ON MOST SMOKERS--
CORNISH HENS.
YOU GOTTA GET YOUR OWN.
YOU'RE OKAY
BY YOURSELF?
ONE OF THE GREAT THINGS
I LOVE ABOUT BARBECUE
IS THAT IT ISN'T ALL THE SAME.
EVERY GREAT JOINT
HAS ITS OWN TWIST,
LIKE OUR NEXT STOP
HERE IN MEMPHIS,
WHERE THEIR BIG DEAL
IS BARBECUED CORNISH HENS.
LET'S CHECK OUT
THE COZY CORNER.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANOTHER PLACE
THAT HAS CORNISH GAME HEN.
THIS IS THE BEST.
IT NEVER CHANGES.
YOU GOTTA GET YOUR OWN.
YOU'RE OKAY
BY YOURSELF?
IT'S EXCEPTIONAL.
IT HAS ITS OWN FLAVOR.
I HAVEN'T SEEN A LOT
OF CORNISH HENS ON MENUS.
THAT'S THE UNIQUE THING
ABOUT, YOU KNOW,
COZY CORNER.
HOWDY!
DESIREE ROBINSON
CAME UP WITH THE IDEA
WITH HER LATE HUSBAND RAYMOND
WHEN HE FIRST OPENED UP HERE
MORE THAN 30 YEARS AGO
AND STARTED SERVING
ALL THE LOCAL FAVORITES.
THIS IS REALLY
TENNESSEE BARBECUE.
AND HOW DID YOU FIND OUT
ABOUT THE COZY CORNER?
A CAB DRIVER, THE GUY
WHO RUNS THE GUEST HOUSE--
PRETTY MUCH EVERYBODY
WE TALKED TO.
SO IF YOU SAID, "BARBECUE,"
THEY SAID, "COZY CORNER."
PRETTY MUCH.
'CAUSE DESIREE'S DOING
EVERYTHING HERE
THE SAME AS ALWAYS.
OUT COMES THE SMOKE.
SAME SMOKER...
THERE GOES THE SMOKE.
SAME SPICY DRY RUB...
CAN I TASTE IT?
SURE.
WITH A SECRET INGREDIENT
FOR SWEETNESS.
THAT'S CAP'N CRUNCH.
OH! WE USE THIS
ON LOTS OF STUFF--
EGGS, CORNBREAD,
BLOODY MARYS.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU ROLL.
OKAY, SHE IS USING IT
ON ALL THE BARBECUE, TOO...
IT'S JUST GREAT.
AND THAT DOES GET US
TO THOSE CORNISH HENS.
SURE MAKE SMALL CHICKENS
HERE IN TENNESSEE.
SO WE JUST SPRINKLE THIS ON.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA
GO ON THE BARBECUE FOR?
UNTIL IT GETS DONE.
OKAY.
I HAVE NEVER DETERMINED
A MEASURE OF HOW LONG,
BECAUSE IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WE GOT--SOMEBODY'S THERE.
THEY'RE TURNING AND WATCHING.
WHEN IT GETS DONE,
THEY TAKE IT OFF.
LOOK AT THAT.
THOSE ARE PRETTY.
THANK YOU.
PULLED RIGHT OFF OF THERE.
MMM. THAT'S TENDER.
I LOVE CORNISH HENS. THEY
HAVE SO MUCH FLAVOR IN 'EM.
SO THE RUB'S
NOT TOO SPICY,
A NICE CRUNCH
TO THE SKIN.
AND WHERE IS THIS IN THE ONE
TO TEN? IS THIS IN THE TOP?
THIS IS TEN.
THIS IS TEN?
RAYMOND HAD IT ON POINT,
DIDN'T HE?
YES, HE DID.
MMM. LET ME FINISH THIS.
I KNOW GOOD BARBECUE,
AND WHOEVER'S BACK THERE
GOT A LOT OF SOUL.
WE'RE DIFFERENT.
WE'RE DIFFERENT?
WE DARE TO BE DIFFERENT.
I HAVE SEEN A LOT OF PIT
MASTERS, A LOT OF BARBECUERS,
BUT WHITE HEAD TO TOE
IN THE SHIRT,
AND NOTHING ON HER
ALL DAY...
THAT MEANS--
THERE'S SOMETHING GOING ON.
SOMETHING GOING ON.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR
THE MEMPHIS BARBECUE TOUR,
BUT DON'T WORRY, WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HE'S GOT THE DOOR LOCKED.
WHOO-WHOO!
ALL ABOARD
THE FLAVOR TRAIN, BABY.
I'M OUTTA HERE.