HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
CHICKEN SOUVLAKI PLATTER.
MANICOTTI PARMIGIANA.
A WORLD OF FLAVORS.
IT'S BIZARRE,
BUT IT'S GOOD.
IT'S LIKE A KETCHUP HOT TUB
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
A PHOENIX JOINT...
ONE OF EACH?
WHERE A BALANCED MEAL
MEETS MEXICAN...
THESE QUESADILLAS
ARE TO DIE FOR.
AND CHINESE...
IS IT MEXICAN
OR ASIAN?
PROBABLY A LITTLE
BIT OF BOTH.
IT'S "MASIAN"?
AND JAMAICAN...
THERE'S JERK CHICKEN, NAMED
AFTER A YET-UNKNOWN CUSTOMER.
ALL ON ONE PLATE...
UNITY.
IT IS VERY UNUSUAL,
BUT THAT'S WHY WE LIKE IT.
GREAT GREEK FOOD
IN A CLASSIC
NEW JERSEY-STYLE DINER...
NOBODY LEAVES HUNGRY
IN THIS PLACE.
THAT'S DOWN HOME IN GEORGIA.
I CAME TO ATLANTA
TO BRING THE CONCEPT HERE.
AND A TINY KITCHEN
IN KANSAS CITY...
(man) WE'RE COOKIN' ON
ELECTRIC--TWO BURNERS.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
YEAH.
WHERE A GLOBE-TRAVELING
ARTIST...
WE REALLY ARE TRYING TO
CHECK OUT THE FOOD, MAN.
IS BRINGING BACK HIS FAVORITES
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD.
LITTLE BIT FROM MOROCCO.
YEAH, LIKE THIS.
LITTLE BIT FROM SPAIN.
LITTLE BIT FROM--YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN I OPENED TEX WASABI'S
SOUTHERN-STYLE BARBEQUE
AND SUSHI RESTAURANT,
PEOPLE THOUGHT I WAS CRAZY.
WELL, IT'S NICE TO COME DOWN
HERE TO PHOENIX, ARIZONA,
AND FIND OUT THAT
THERE'S ANOTHER GROUP
THAT'S OFF THE HOOK
AND OUT-OF-BOUNDS
SERVING CHINESE AND MEXICAN.
WELCOME...
TO CHINO BANDIDO.
IT'S BIZARRE, BUT IT'S GOOD.
ORDER UP!
EGG FOO YUNG.
(Guy) YOU SHOULD
CALL THIS EGG-FOO-FUN.
IT IS VERY UNUSUAL,
BUT THAT'S WHY WE
LIKE IT.
CHINESE FOOD
IN A QUESADILLA.
(Guy) THAT'S AWESOME.
THE UNITY,
THE BONDING.
(woman) LOVE IT.
YOU WON'T FIND
ANOTHER PLACE LIKE IT.
IT COMES FROM THE CULTURE
OF THE FAMILY THAT OWNS IT.
ONE OF EACH?
THAT WOULD BE ARIZONA NATIVES
EVE AND FRANK COLLINS...
HI, SIR,
HOW YOU DOIN'?
WHO OPENED THIS PLACE
17 YEARS AGO.
BEFORE WE OPENED IT,
WE SAT UP IN BED,
AND SHE SAID,
"WHAT ARE WE GONNA SERVE?"
AND I SAID, "WELL, WE'LL
SERVE WHAT WE EAT AT HOME."
THAT MEANT THE MEXICAN FOOD
THAT'S SO BIG IN ARIZONA...
HONEY, QUESADILLA.
OKAY, THANK YOU.
THE CHINESE FOOD
EVE GREW UP WITH...
THE CHINESE BARBEQUE
COMES FROM MY MOM AND DAD.
AND THE CARIBBEAN FOOD SOME
FRIENDS TURNED THEM ON TO.
THERE'S JERK CHICKEN, NAMED
AFTER A YET-UNKNOWN CUSTOMER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S AMAZING.
AND THEN,
THEY PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
YOU CAN HAVE MEXICAN,
CARIBBEAN,
OR YOU HAVE CHINESE OR
A COMBINATION OF EVERYTHING,
AND IT'S JUST SO COOL.
I CAN CREATE A WHOLE
NEW COMBINATION
THAT I'VE NEVER EVEN
HAD BEFORE.
LIKE CARNITAS NEXT
TO JADE RED CHICKEN,
JERK FRIED RICE
AND CUBAN BLACK BEANS,
A BURRITO FILLED
WITH CHINESE JEN RED PORK,
NEXT TO PORK FRIED RICE,
JAMAICAN JERK CHICKEN,
AND REFRIED BEANS.
CHINESE EMERALD CHICKEN
WITH MACHACA,
REFRIED BEANS
AND JERK FRIED RICE.
IT IS ODD,
BUT IT TASTES VERY GOOD.
SIMPLE FOOD, REALLY.
MAYBE TO COOK...
VEGGIE QUESADILLA.
BUT TRY ORDERING.
YOU CAN GET 96,420
DIFFERENT COMBINATIONS
THE BARBEQUE PORK QUESADILLA
WITH THE TERIYAKI CHICKEN,
BLACK BEANS
AND JERK FRIED RICE.
I'LL MAKE YOU AN EXPERT
AT CHINO BANDIDO.
THE COMBINATION
IS RICE AND BEANS
AND ANY TWO
OF THESE NUMBERS.
PUT JUST THE NUMBER,
IT'S A PILE ON THE PLATE.
"B" IS BURRITO.
"Q" IS QUESADILLA.
MARK YOUR BEANS--
BLACK OR REFRIED?
MARK YOUR RICE.
THERE ARE WHITE,
JERK FRIED, PORK FRIED
PLAIN FRIED AND CHICKEN FRIED.
LET'S SAY YOU LIKE NUMBER 1
AND YOU LIKE NUMBER 7.
IT'S A 1Q AND A 7.
ANYBODY DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND?
DOUBLE JERK CHICKEN COMBO,
1 AND A QUESADILLA,
BLACK BEANS
AND JERK FRIED RICE.
THERE WASN'T EVEN
A HESITATION.
AND THERE'S SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY.
I'M HAVING JADE RED
CHICKEN WITH RICE.
UH, JADE RED QUESADILLA.
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET,
AND IT'S GOT A NICE,
SPICY KICK TO IT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
RED SAUCE
FOR JADE RED CHICKEN.
I GET SESAME OIL, SOME RED
CHILI OIL 'CAUSE OF THE COLOR.
WHAT ELSE IS IN THERE?
THERE'S A SECRET OIL.
YOU GONNA TELL ME?
NO.
TOMATO SAUCE.
RIGHT INTO THE OIL?
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WE FRY IT, MM-HMM.
DO YOU SEE THIS?
AND WE PUT THE GARLIC IN.
THE OIL INTO--
WHY?
IT FORMS A GLAZE.
IT'S LIKE A KETCHUP
HOT TUB IN FLAVOR TOWN.
IT IS.
THIS IS SUGAR.
POWDERED SUGAR?
POWDERED SUGAR.
AND LET THAT BOIL.
POP THE GREEN ONIONS IN.
I AM JUST IN AWE.
AND THAT'LL BOIL DOWN.
(whistles)
SO WE HAVE THIGH MEAT,
EGG WHITES, CORNSTARCH.
DOES THIS HELP KEEP
THE CORNSTARCH OFF THE--
SO IT DOESN'T GET SO DENSE.
YEP.
OH, I'M EXCITED.
A LITTLE GARLIC SALT.
AND YOU PUT IT IN THERE
VERSUS IN THE CORNSTARCH.
YES, SO IT'LL BE
NICE AND LIGHT.
YOU WILL SEE THIS
ON "GUY'S BIG BITE."
HAS TO BE PURE CORNSTARCH.
PURE. NO FLOUR.
NOT A DERIVATIVE.
SHAKE IT UP.
WHOA!
POP IT OVER HERE
AND DROP IT IN.
IT'S THE VOLUMIZING
OF THE EGG WHITES.
YES.
ISN'T THAT PRETTY?
OKAY, SO NOW WE GET
THE SAUCE WE MADE.
RIGHT, WHEN IT'S BOILING HOT,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS CHICKEN.
I'M GONNA WEAR LIKE
A JUMPSUIT NEXT TIME.
YEP.
YOU ONLY LOOK LIKE YOU'VE
DONE THAT 900,000 TIMES.
YEAH.
THAT'S YOUR RED CHICKEN.
OH, THAT'S GONNA BE HOT.
IT'S VERY HOT.
OR LIKE RYDER WOULD SAY,
"MMM-NUM-NUM."
IT'S GLAZED.
IT'S HOT.
OH!
THAT'S AWESOME.
HOWEVER YOU GET IT--
WITH RICE, IN A BURRITO,
OR A QUESADILLA.
SO GOOD WITH
ALL THE CHEESE.
(Guy) WERE YOU ALWAYS IN
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS?
NO.
YOU NEVER--
I BURNED RICE
UNTIL I WAS 20.
BUT NOTHIN'S BURNIN' NOW.
THESE QUESADILLAS
ARE TO DIE FOR.
THE FUSION
OF THE MEXICAN/CHINESE FOOD
WORKS WELL TOGETHER.
I HAVE A LITTLE
OF MACHACA HERE.
IT'S DELICATELY SPICED.
IT'S MEXICAN SHREDDED BEEF,
BUT LOOK HOW THEY'RE DOIN' IT.
(Eve) THIS IS WHERE
THE CHINESE STYLE COMES IN.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS COOKS OVER HIGH HEAT...
RIGHT.
AND THEN YOU'RE
DOING IT QUICKLY.
THIS GETS SERVED
IN QUESADILLAS,
IN BURRITOS AND
WITH CHINESE FRIED RICE.
LOOK WHAT I HAPPEN TO HAVE--
A RANDOM FORK.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYBODY IN THERE.
MMM, GREAT TEXTURE
TO THE MEAT.
BIG GARLIC--
DYNAMITE.
YOU WANT TO TALK DYNAMITE?
THERE'S FIRE
AND "POW" IN YOUR MOUTH
THE WHOLE TIME
YOU'RE EATING.
THERE'S JAMAICAN JERK CHICKEN.
NOT ONLY IS IT HOT, BUT IT
HAS A REALLY GREAT FLAVOR.
AND THIS ONE.
THE POLLO DIABLO CHICKEN.
IT'S PRETTY HOT.
(Guy) AND WHO MADE UP
THIS RECIPE?
(Eve) IT CAME FROM
A CHINESE RESTAURANT.
I USED TO DO IT
WITH CALAMARI AND SHRIMP.
AND THE SERRANOS.
SEEDS AND ALL?
THAT'S WHAT GIVES IT
THE REAL KICK--
THE REAL FLAVOR,
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED.
SO THEN WE TAKE THE GARLIC, YOUR
ONION AND YOUR GREEN ONION,
AND THEN YOUR SERRANOS.
I TONED IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU HAD TO GRINGO-IZE IT.
FOR THE GRINGOS.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
GARLIC SALT. THIS SITS
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS,
AND THEN WE COMBINE IT
WITH THE CHICKEN.
(Guy) HOT WOK?
(Eve) HOT WOK.
COLD OIL.
FOOD WON'T STICK.
YOU'RE GONNA FRY IT.
PUT THE GREEN ONION IN.
DIDN'T EXPECT THIS ON
"DINERS," DID YA?
LITTLE TOUCH OF GARLIC SALT
AT THE VERY END.
BRINGS THAT FLAVOR OUT.
MMM. WOW.
WOW!
THE CRUNCH IS FANTASTIC.
THE FRESH GREEN ONIONS
MIXED IN WITH THE MIXTURE
OF THE SERRANOS
AND THE GARLIC--
I MEAN, THAT'S
JUST MASSIVE FLAVOR.
WINNER, WINNER,
CHICKEN DINNER.
NOW YOU KNOW WHY WE COME HERE
EVERY TIME WE'RE IN TOWN.
WE'RE HOOKED ON THE FOOD.
ALL YOU GOTTA DO
IS TRY THE FOOD ONE TIME
AND THAT--
THAT'LL SELL YA.
DOES IT SAY
"BODY BY CHINOS"?
IT DOES.
I MADE IT.
LOYAL,
VERY LOYAL.
THIS IS JUST HANDS DOWN--
I'VE BEEN LOOK SO FORWARD
TO COMING HERE.
IT'S REMARKABLE.
IT'S PROBABLY ONE OF
THE NEATEST PLACES
THAT WE'VE SHOT ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
AW, THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
CHICKEN SOUVLAKI PLATTER.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO GEORGIA...
WE'RE ALWAYS LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
AND WE FOUND IT.
FOR DINER CLASSICS
FROM EVERYWHERE.
PAELLA AT
2:00 IN THE MORNING.
YOUR FRIEND CAN HAVE
SCRAMBLED EGGS.
WELL, HERE'S
A CLASSIC ONE FOR YA--
A BIG, SHINY STEEL DINER
RUN BY A BIG, EXTENDED FAMILY
WITH A HUGE MENU FULL
OF ALL KINDS OF FOOD,
ESPECIALLY GREEK.
NOW YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND
A DINER LIKE THIS WHERE?
IN JERSEY OR PHILLY?
NAH, BUT WE'RE DOWN SOUTH.
WELCOME TO MARIETTA, GEORGIA.
CHICKEN SOUVLAKI PLATTER.
MANICOTTI PARMIGIANA...
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
ETHNIC FOOD,
AMERICAN FOOD.
BEEF STROGANOFF.
THIS IS WONDERFUL,
AND I'M JUST HAPPY.
SPANAKOPITA.
EXCELLENT.
INTERNATIONAL FLAVOR TO IT.
PAELLA AT 2:00
IN THE MORNING.
YOUR FRIEND CAN HAVE
SCRAMBLED EGGS.
THE EVEN BIGGER DEAL IS
THAT IT'S HERE IN GEORGIA.
I CAME TO ATLANTA
TO BRING THE CONCEPT HERE.
GUS TSELIOS
GREW UP IN A BIG DINER FAMILY
NEAR NEW YORK CITY...
ENJOYING YOUR BREAKFAST?
WITH MOM, DAD, COUSINS,
EVEN HEAD CHEF UNCLE GUS.
I KNOW THEM FROM NEW YORK
FOR 20 YEARS.
SO JUST OUT OF HIGH SCHOOL...
AT THE RIPE AGE
IN PROFESSIONAL
RESTAURANTING AT 18.
HE BROUGHT 'EM ALL DOWN SOUTH
CLOSE TO ATLANTA
AND OPENED THE MARIETTA DINER.
AND I NOTICED THE CITY
DEFINITELY NEEDS A DINER
THAT, UH, SERVES EVERYTHING
24 HOURS A DAY.
OH, MY GOD.
WE'RE ABOUT 2,500,
3,000 PEOPLE A DAY.
IS IT FREE FOOD,
OR WHAT--
IT'S JUST GOOD FOOD
AND FAST.
(man) WANDA, PICK UP.
WANDA.
IT'S A GREEK DINER
WITH ALL KINDS OF FOOD.
AND TONS OF GREEK FAVORITES
LIKE GYROS,
SKEWERS CALLED SOUVLAKI,
GRAPE LEAVES,
HOMEMADE BAKLAVA,
A KIND OF GREEK LASAGNA
CALLED PASTICCIO,
AND GREEK SPINACH PIES HANDED
OUT LIKE DINNER ROLLS.
YOU GET A FREE LITTLE
PIECE OF SPANAKOPITA.
IT'S LIKE A GREEK TOUCH.
OKAY, SO HOW DO
WE MAKE IT?
MELT OUR BUTTER.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
NOW WE TAKE OUR ONIONS,
FRESH SCALLIONS, FRESH DILL.
BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE NUTMEG.
REALLY?
LITTLE SALT--WE MAKE, LIKE,
30, 40 TRAYS A DAY
OF SPANAKOPITA.
30 OR 40 A DAY?
TRAYS A DAY.
GO. GOT OUR SPINACH
OVER HERE.
WANT ME TO GET ALL
THE STUFF ON THE BOTTOM?
YEAH, THAT'S OUR FLAVOR.
GONNA ADD OUR FETA CHEESE.
NOW WE PUT OUR EGGS.
THAT'S THE BINDER.
YEP.
AND NOW WE'RE
GOING TO LAYER
800,000 SHEETS
OF PHYLLO DOUGH.
NO CHEATING.
NO TWO AT A TIME.
LITTLE MORE.
LET'S GO.
OH, SORRY.
PERFECT.
CROOKED LINES
ARE OKAY?
YOU GOTTA GIVE ME
SOME ROOM HERE.
WE TAKE A LITTLE WATER
AND BLESS THE SPINACH PIE.
OTHERWISE THE FIRST
INITIAL HEAT RIGHT ON TOP
WILL SEPARATE EVERYTHING
TOO FAST.
EXACTLY.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW IS THERE A WAY THAT YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO ENJOY THIS?
JUST GRAB IT LIKE A PIZZA.
I CAN GET IN LIKE
THE CHEESESTEAK ARMCHAIR.
THERE YOU GO.
SEE, YOU GET DOWN.
THE FINGER--THE INTERWEAVE.
OH, MAN,
THAT IS EXCELLENT.
MAN, THAT'S GREAT FLAVOR.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
(grunts)
FLAKY WITH CHEESE INSIDE.
ABSOLUTELY EXCELLENT.
WHAT ARE WE ENJOYING HERE?
I CAN'T PRONOUNCE IT,
BUT IT'S GREEK LASAGNA.
PASTICCIO.
WHAT IS IT?
YEAH, WHATEVER.
A GREEK VERSION
OF A LASAGNA.
THIS IS GUS'S RECIPE?
YES.
I WILL DO THE OLIVE OIL,
THE ONION.
I WILL DO MY GARLIC.
HE'S LIKE SPEED CHEF.
CINNAMON STICK.
BAY LEAF.
HEY, WHAT ARE WE,
ON "IRON CHEF" RIGHT NOW?
NOW I PUT MY
GROUND BEEF.
I AM GLAD THAT NONE OF
MY PERSONAL BELONGINGS
WERE SITTING
ON THAT COUNTER.
AND NOW WE'RE
GONNA COOK PASTA.
LITTLE WHITE WINE?
YES, SIR.
LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
LITTLE SALT, TOMATO PUREE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START MAKIN'
THE BéCHAMEL.
PUT MILK...
WHITE PEPPER.
A LITTLE NUTMEG?
A LITTLE BIT SUGAR.
SO NOW WE START
ADDING THE ROUX?
IT WILL START
BECOMING THICK.
WOW.
ONE DROP LITTLE
BIT BOUILLON.
AND THE EGG IS GONNA MAKE
IT A LITTLE MORE TIGHTER.
FASTER, FASTER, FASTER.
OTHERWISE, WE'RE GONNA
MAKE AN OMELET
INSIDE OF THIS.
GREAT, WE DROP PASTA
IN THE BOWL.
WE CAN DROP COUPLE EGGS
IN THERE.
LITTLE BIT NUTMEG MORE.
WHITE PEPPER, OKAY?
PARMESAN CHEESE.
I FEEL LIKE WE'RE
LATE FOR A BANQUET.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA DROP
LITTLE BIT BéCHAMEL INTO.
AND REALLY TIGHTEN IT
ALL TOGETHER.
IF YOU GET IN HIS WAY,
YOU COULD LOSE AN ARM.
NOW THAT IS HOT.
LITTLE PARMESAN?
GIVES 'EM NICE COLOR.
OKAY, "UNCLE GUS GONE WILD,"
WE'RE GONNA PUT
IT IN THE OVEN?
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT. (whistles)
UH, YEAH, HOT.
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
AND THE PASTA'S NICE
AND AL DENTE IN THERE.
IT'S NOT OVERCOOKED.
YOU KNOW WHAT FLAVOR
I GET RIGHT OFF THE BAT?
THE NUTMEG.
HOW DID YOU KNOW I
WAS GONNA SAY NUTMEG?
WELL, I THINK I KNOW
WHAT YOU EATING.
MMM.
UNBELIEVABLE.
WE ALWAYS LOOK FOR SOMETHIN'
A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
AND WE FOUND IT.
RIGHT HERE IN
MARIETTA, GEORGIA.
I DROVE UP AND I SEE THIS
GLOWING, STAINLESS--
I MEAN, THE WOODWORK,
THE LIGHTING.
IT'S FIRST RATE.
THIS IS MY PASSION.
I LOVE--I LOVE WHAT I DO.
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU COULDN'T FINISH?
OF COURSE NOT.
YOU KNOW BETTER THAN THAT.
THEIR MENU IS LIKE A BOOK.
WITH CHAPTERS FROM EVERYWHERE.
(Gus) 400 OR 500 ITEMS.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH AND DINNER,
24 HOURS A DAY.
FROM GREEK TO ITALIAN.
FETTUCCINE CARBONARA.
THE FETTUCCINE ALFREDO
IS EXCELLENT.
BEEF STROGANOFF
COMIN' UP.
PICASSO, ARE
YOU FINISHED?
YES, SIR.
SO DEEP IN FLAVOR,
SO RICH.
HOW'S THE MATZO BALL SOUP?
GOOD. EXCELLENT.
BEST MATZO BALL SOUP
SOUTH OF BROOKLYN.
HERE'S YOUR PAELLA.
I KNOW MY PAELLA.
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
DOES THIS FEED?
NOBODY LEAVES HUNGRY
IN THIS PLACE.
SOME OLIVE OIL.
WE START WITH THE CHICKEN.
LITTLE DREDGE ON THERE--
ON THE CHICKEN.
NOW WE GET SALMON.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THE PORTION ALREADY!
NOW WE PUT OUR
LOBSTER TAILS.
LOOK AT THOSE.
OUR SCALLOPS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT SHRIMPS OVER HERE.
TURN MY SALMON A LITTLE BIT.
GARLIC.
(moans)
NICE LITTLE SEAR
ON THE SCALLOPS.
A LITTLE
CAJUN SEASONING.
NOW WE'LL END
IT UP WITH MUSSELS.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKIN'
PAELLA FOR A PARTY OF TEN.
ONE DROP OF WINE,
FRESH BASIL.
NICE.
CHOPPED CLAMS HERE.
DROP A LITTLE SCAMPI SAUCE.
BUTTER, WHITE WINE...
YES, SIR.
AND GARLIC.
LITTLE LEMON JUICE
INSIDE AND LITTLE TABASCO.
NOW A LITTLE
MARINARA SAUCE.
THIS IS ONE
UNIQUE PAELLA, MAN.
COGNAC FOR A NICE FLAVOR.
I WANT TO KNOW HOW THAT MADE
IT INTO THE DISH, UNCLE GUS.
(chuckles)
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU COOK, BUDDY.
OKAY, SIR.
A LITTLE SAFFRON RICE?
PUT RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
YOU'RE NOT JUST GONNA
POUR IT ON THERE?
NO, I'M NOT.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE
2,000 MEALS, BUT WE'RE GONNA
PLATE EVERY ONE UP LIKE IT'S
GONNA GO TO THE PRESIDENT.
YES, SIR.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I WANT TO EAT IT
OR HAVE MY PICTURE
TAKEN WITH IT.
MMM.
GREAT FLAVOR,
INDIVIDUAL FLAVOR.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'D LIKE TO ENJOY
RIGHT AFTER EATING
SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WHAT?
A NAP.
THAT'D BE REAL NICE.
LITTLE SOMEWHERE
TO LAY DOWN, GUS.
READ ME A STORY,
UNCLE GUS.
WHEN I'M EATING MY PAELLA,
I'M DOIN' REAL GOOD.
ANY DISH I HAVE EVER HAD HERE
IS JUST SPECTACULAR.
IT'S THE PERFECT PLACE.
I THOUGHT THAT JERSEY
WAS THE DINER CAPITAL.
YOU HAVEN'T BEEN
TO ATLANTA YET. (whistles)
I'M UNCLE GUS.
I'M DRIVIN' THE BUS
TO THE FLAVOR TOWN.
I GOTTA GET
AN UNCLE GUS.
COMIN' UP...
YOU HUNGRY?
A TINY JOINT IN KANSAS CITY
WITH BIG FLAVORS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD.
(man) IT'S LIKE YOUR MOM'S
HOME COOKING
IF SHE WERE COOKING
SOMETHING FROM GUATEMALA.
ONE OF THE THINGS
WE SAY ON "TRIPLE D"
IS THAT IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
SO HERE WE ARE IN KANSAS CITY,
AND LOOK WHAT WE FOUND--
Y.J.'s SNACK BAR.
CHECK IT OUT.
(woman) IT'S IN THERE.
(Gus) LOOK AT THAT.
I HAVE SOME YUMMY,
SPICY FOOD.
WE GET REFERRED TO MOSTLY
AS A THIRD-WORLD SNACK BAR.
(man) IT'S LIKE YOUR
MOM'S HOME COOKING
IF SHE WERE COOKING
SOMETHING FROM GUATEMALA.
IS THIS DONE
IN PLATINUM NEON?
YES. YES, IT IS.
YOU HUNGRY?
DAVID FORD IS DISHIN' IT UP
FROM A CLOSET-SIZED KITCHEN...
WE'RE COOKIN'
ON ELECTRIC--TWO BURNER.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
YEAH.
AND A SIDEWALK GRILL.
(David) THERE'S A PERFECT
BIRD, RIGHT THERE.
WHATEVER HE MAKES
IS OKAY WITH ME.
THAT SAMBAL GIVES YOU
A NICE COLOR ON IT.
THIS SELF-TAUGHT COOK BROUGHT
BACK HIS FAVORITE DISHES
FROM HIS WORLD TRAVELS.
(David) I GOT
AN AFRICAN SUPPLIER.
I GOT A LATIN SUPPLIER.
I GOT A MIDDLE EASTERN SUPPLIER.
FROM MOROCCO.
I THOUGHT IT WAS DELICIOUS.
IT'S DIFFERENT EVERY DAY.
THE WAY THE FOOD
GOT FIGURED OUT
IS WHAT I WANTED
TO EAT.
SO YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT
THE CHALKBOARD
TO KNOW WHAT'S COOKIN'.
SOME DAYS,
IT'S MAYAN TOSTADAS
OR NORTH AFRICAN LAMB KABOBS
WITH COUSCOUS,
TURKISH STUFFED FIGS
OR...
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
MEXICAN-STYLE FISH
IN BANANA LEAVES.
I LOVE IT.
DAVID MAKES THIS
REGULARLY.
(David) BANANA LEAVES.
IT'S GONNA GIVE YOU A LITTLE
BIT OF EARTHY FLAVOR,
AND IT'S ALSO GOT AN OIL
IN THE LEAF.
THIS HAS GOT ROSEMARY
IN THE OLIVE OIL,
AND THESE ARE JUST DRIED
ORANGE PEELS, BUT IT'LL ADD
JUST A LITTLE EXTRA
TO THE FISH.
A LITTLE CITRUS TO IT?
THESE ARE BURRO BANANAS
INSTEAD OF PLANTAINS.
WE GOT SOME SLICED LEMON,
SO WE'RE BASICALLY
JUST GETTING A LOT OF FRUIT
AND CITRUS AS A BASE
DOWN ON THIS TO START WITH.
THEN SOME GARLIC,
FRESH VEGETABLES,
AND TILAPIA.
TILAPIA'S SUCH A NICE,
FIRM, DENSE FISH.
YOU'VE GOT SOME GOOD MOISTURE
COMIN' OUT OF THE BANANAS.
THE CITRUS--
THERE'S A TON THERE.
THE TOMATILLOS WILL
GIVE SOME OFF,
AND NOW YOU THROW
THAT MUCH ONION IN--
WE'RE GONNA BE THERE.
WE'RE THERE.
I'M FEELIN' PRETTY
GOOD ABOUT THAT.
THIS IS ZA'ATAR.
THIS IS A CLASSIC
MIDDLE EASTERN SPICE.
THAT'S A COMBINATION
OF THYME AND SESAME SEEDS.
AND DAVID'S OWN FISH RUB
WITH A TARRAGON BASE.
YOU GET A LITTLE
SPRINKLE OF THAT ON.
I'M GONNA PUT A COUPLE
OF OLIVES IN EACH ONE.
THE LEAF OF AN AVOCADO TREE, AND
IT ADDS KIND OF AN ANISE FLAVOR,
A LICORICE FLAVOR TO IT.
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA WANT TO DO
NOW IS JUST WRAP THESE UP,
MAKE IT LOOK GOOD
RIGHT ON THE TOP, HUH?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
STAR FRUIT.
HOW LONG DOES
THAT GO DOWN?
WE'RE GONNA DO THIS ABOUT
12 MINUTES, 14 MINUTES.
WOW.
MMM.
THAT HAS A REAL
NICE ESSENCE.
PICKS UP A LITTLE HERB.
YOU GOT A LITTLE VINEGAR
COMIN' OFF THE OLIVES.
LITTLE ROSEMARY
STANDS OUT THERE.
WOW, THAT WAS GOOD.
THE FISH WAS EXCELLENT.
WE LOVE EVERYTHING HERE.
EVERYTHING TASTES WONDERFUL.
YOU'VE BEEN
TO CULINARY SCHOOL?
NO. NO, NO, NO.
HE'S A SELF-TAUGHT COOK--
ACTUALLY, AN ARTIST...
YOU WANT TO HAVE THAT
FOR HERE OR TO GO?
WHO HAPPENED TO BE LIVING
ABOVE THE RESTAURANT.
THIS SHOP HAD BEEN OPEN
FOR 60, 65 YEARS ALREADY.
PUTS A SIGN ON THE WINDOW.
SAYS "DELI BUSINESS FOR SALE."
I SAID, "NO, THIS'LL BE GOOD.
"I'LL PUT IN
A CAPPUCCINO MACHINE.
"I'M ALREADY FEEDIN' 20 ARTISTS
UPSTAIRS IN MY HOUSE EVERY WEEK.
I CAN CHARGE 'EM NOW."
AND FEED 'EM FAVORITE DISHES
FROM HIS TRAVELS
THROUGH LATIN AMERICA, ASIA
AND THE MEDITERRANEAN.
(man) THE MID-EAST PLATE
JUST CAN'T BE BEAT.
IT'S JUST FANTASTIC.
WE'RE GONNA BE TAKIN' A LITTLE
TOUR AROUND THE MEDITERRANEAN,
LITTLE BIT FROM MOROCCO.
YEAH, LIKE THIS.
A LITTLE BIT FROM SPAIN.
A LITTLE BIT FROM--YEAH.
I'M BACK.
LIVIN' IT.
YOU'RE THERE.
WE GOT SOME MEDJOOL DATES
RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE CHEESE--
CHEESE ALL THE WAY.
GET A FULL THUMBFUL OF IT.
YEAH.
CAME ACROSS THAT IN GRANADA,
IN SPAIN.
IT'S AN EXCELLENT
AGED PROSCIUTTO.
THOSE LITTLE PIGGIES THERE.
YEAH, THESE AREN'T GONNA
BE BAD AT ALL.
SO WE'RE GONNA PICK
THIS UP AND PUT IT
IN THE CHORIZO OVER HERE.
I'M READY.
MMM.
RICH.
I LOVE THAT.
A LITTLE COLD SHERRY WOULD BE
REALLY GOOD WITH THIS.
COLD BEER.
COLD BEER, YEP.
NOT A BAD IDEA,
SINCE HE'S SERVING
IT UP WITH HUMMUS
SPICED WITH
A HOT ASIAN CHILI SAUCE.
HERE, MAN, GIVE THAT A TRY.
WOW, THERE'S A LITTLE HEAT--
THERE'S A LITTLE HEAT
DOWN IN THERE.
YEAH, IT COMES UP.
IT COMES UP.
NOT IN THE FRONT.
IT'S ALWAYS IN THE BACK.
IT WARMS UP ON YOU.
I GUESS THE TASTING'S OVER.
HE'S ALSO THROWING IN
A THAI-SPICED CHICKEN.
(David) THAT'S A SWEET
THAI BASIL.
SUPER-SPICY,
HOT RED CHILI OIL.
WE'RE GONNA ADD JUST A TOUCH
OF THE SESAME OIL,
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF DRIED THYME AND SESAME,
AND I THINK PROBABLY
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS TURMERIC
WILL BE GOOD.
YOU JUST KIND OF
MASSAGE THOSE TOGETHER?
JUST KIND OF MASSAGE
THEM A LITTLE BIT.
JUST OVER MEDIUM ON THAT.
MEAT GRILLS A LOT BETTER
WHEN YOU PUT IT ON THE GRILL
AT ROOM TEMPERATURE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M DOWN WITH THAT
SAME IDEA, BROTHER.
LOOK AT IT
AND MAKE SURE
THE JUICES ARE RUNNIN'
CLEAR ON THIS.
YOU'RE PERFECT.
THERE'S A PERFECT BIRD
RIGHT THERE.
AND HE'S PUTTIN' IT ALL
TOGETHER WITH SOME OLIVES
AND FRESH FETA CHEESE.
(David) SOME GOOD
MIDDLE EASTERN YOGURT.
GONNA WANT TO HAVE
A LITTLE HARISSA.
IT'S A TRADITIONAL MIDDLE
EASTERN HOT SAUCE.
RIGHT NOW, WE CAN GET
POMEGRANATES IN SEASON,
SO WE'LL JUST GET A COUPLE OF
SEEDS RIGHT ON THE TOP THERE.
LET'S GO EAT THIS.
LET'S EAT IT.
I THINK THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
YOU KNOW, DO YOU KIND OF
JUST BUILD AS YOU GO?
KIND OF THROW IT DOWN
HOW YOU LIKE?
MM-HMM.
HERE WE GO.
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S TASTY.
NOT BAD.
WOW, THAT'S HOT.
YEAH, THE HARISSA IS HOT.
WHAT COUNTRY AM I
IN RIGHT NOW?
YOU'RE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE MID COUNTRY.
IT HAS THAT KIND OF
THIRD-WORLD AMBIENCE.
AND SOME FROM DOWN HOME, TOO.
THIS IS JAMBALAYA.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
DAVID'S COOKIN'
THE LOUISIANA WAY.
MMM, THAT'S TASTY.
AT Y.J.'s SNACK BAR
IN KANSAS CITY...
HEY, ERIK.
EVERYONE KNOWS EVERYONE.
IT'S JUST SO COMFORTABLE.
YOU HUNGRY?
AND FOR TEN YEARS NOW,
OWNER DAVID FORD'S
BEEN CRANKIN' OUT PERSONAL
FAVORITES HE FELL IN LOVE WITH
WHILE TRAVELING THE WORLD.
WE REALLY ARE TRYING TO CHECK
OUT THE FOOD, MAN.
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
MOROCCO, SPAIN,
GUATEMALA.
IT'S GOOD.
BUT HE'S ALSO CHASIN'
BIG FLAVORS CLOSER TO HOME.
WE GO TO NEW ORLEANS
A COUPLE TIMES A YEAR.
AND THAT INSPIRED THIS.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
WHERE I COME FROM,
WE CALL THIS JAMBALAYA.
YEAH.
JAMBALAYA.
YEAH. WELL, IT SAYS
DIRTY RICE UP THERE.
DIRTY RICE...
IS A JAMBALAYA.
IT'S A JAMBALAYA.
FIRST THING WE WANT
TO DO IS WE WANT TO GET
SOME SALT IN
THE BOILING WATER.
SO WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A STOCK
OUT OF WHOLE BIRD?
ABSOLUTELY.
THIS IS OUR SOUP BASE THAT WE'RE
NORMALLY WORKIN' WITH.
THIS HAS GO A LITTLE DEHYDRATED
ONION AND DEHYDRATED CELERY.
WE NEED TO GET THE VEGGIES
DOWN WITH THE CHICKEN
IN THE BIG METAL HOT TUB.
RIGHT, SO WE'LL MIX UP
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER
IN THERE, RIGHT?
SOME WHITE PEPPER
IN ON TOP OF IT.
WE GOT SOME CAYENNE PEPPER.
THEN WE GOT SOME CUMIN.
THIS IS THE MAGIC BLEND?
THIS IS A LITTLE BIT
OF THE MAGIC.
THAT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
HERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT, HOW'S THAT LUNCH
TODAY? IS THAT GOOD?
WE'RE JUST GONNA
GET THESE ON,
LET 'EM GET
A NICE FLAVOR ON IT.
WE'RE WORKIN' A CAJUN SAUSAGE
AND AN ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
WOW. SO EVERYBODY'S
READY TO BE CUT UP.
YOU WANT A PIECE OF THAT?
YOU WANT TO TRY IT?
I THINK I PROBABLY SHOULD,
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW,
CULINARILY I, UH--
YEAH, WELL,
YOU GOTTA BE ABLE
TO TEST EVERYTHING
THAT YOU'RE SERVING.
SO WE CAN JUST PULL
THIS BIRD OUT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ALSO ADD AT THIS POINT
A LITTLE BIT OF
TOMATO SAUCE IN THERE.
THESE MEATS--WE'RE GONNA
INTEGRATE THOSE IN THERE.
JUST GONNA GET THE RICE UP TO
THE RIGHT LEVEL IN HERE.
THAT'S STIRRED UP.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME
HOT SAUCE ON THAT.
SET IT AND FORGET IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM, THAT IS TASTY.
THERE'S REALLY
SOMETHING TO BE SAID
ABOUT GRILLIN' IT
BEFORE YOU PUT IT IN.
OH, YEAH.
(laughs)
OKAY, IS THAT
A LITTLE SWEAT UP THERE?
I GOT LITTLE BEADS
OF SWEAT COMIN' DOWN.
I LOVE THIS--
TINY KITCHEN, BIG MENU.
OUTSTANDING.
PEOPLE ARE HANGIN' OUT.
IT'S NICE.
SORRY, BUT I GOTTA
CLEAN UP MY PLATE.
NICE COOKIN'
WITH YOU, MAN.
YEP, RIGHT ON.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS IS GONNA
GET GOOD NOW.
(mumbles)
WHOA!
WOW!
(together) ♪ MERRILY, MERRILY,
MERRILY, MERRILY ♪
♪ GOT YOUR FETA CHEESE ♪
HEY!