HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LOVE THE CORNBREAD.
TRADITIONAL DISHES...
MMM.
TRIPLE "D" STYLE.
THE FOOD'S AWESOME.
THEY ARE GOIN' HOT.
THE MARYLAND FAVORITE...
MMM, DELICIOUS.
THAT'S BEEN
A SMASH HIT FOREVER...
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO STEAM CRAB?
MY FATHER.
AT A PLACE BY THE WATER...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
WHERE THE CRAB
JUST KEEPS ON COMING.
JUMBO LUMP CRABMEAT,
CRAB PRETZEL
AND A CRAB BALL.
HANG OUT LONG ENOUGH,
THEY'LL FEED YOU.
IN TENNESSEE...
THIS IS THE TASTE
OF MEMPHIS.
SOUTHERN FAVORITES...
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
DONE MOM'S WAY...
HOMEMADE--
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GOOD.
WHATEVER YOU CALL IT.
I'VE ALWAYS
CALLED IT "CHOW-CHOW."
BUT I CALL IT
THE "CHA-CHA-CHA,"
YOU KNOW, LIKE
YOU'RE DOING LIKE THIS.
AND IN MINNESOTA...
SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALL.
ITALIAN-AMERICAN COOKING...
THE PASTA IS MADE FRESH HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE WAY HIS FAMILY'S
BEEN DOING IT FOREVER.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
EXCELLENT.
EVERY BIT
OF IT'S HOMEMADE.
(Guy) WELL, YOU'RE NOT
SKIMPING ON THE CHEESE.
MMM. WHOOP, WHOOP.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN YOU'RE IN MARYLAND
AND YOU'RE THINKING
TRADITIONAL FOOD,
WELL, YOU'RE PROBABLY
THINKING CRAB,
ESPECIALLY THE WAY
THEY STEAM 'EM
AND DUMP A PILE OF THEM
ON BUTCHER PAPER
AND EVERYBODY DIVES IN.
SO I'M 20 MINUTES SOUTH
OF BALTIMORE,
ROLLING IN FOR WHAT THEY CALL
A CRAB FEAST
AT A PLACE CALLED
THE STONEY CREEK INN.
MMM, DELICIOUS.
PERFECTLY SEASONED
MARYLAND CRAB.
WILL YOU GUYS
EAT ALL THIS?
(woman) PROBABLY.
AND FORGET
THE SOCIAL GRACES.
GETTING YOUR HANDS DIRTY
IS ALL PART OF THE GAME.
DO YOU BREAK 'EM
AND SELF-CLEAN 'EM RIGHT HERE?
(woman) YEAH.
YOU MADE A TREMENDOUS MESS.
THAT'S BECAUSE I MAKE SURE
I EAT ALL MINE.
(woman) LOOK AT THAT.
YOU LICK THAT OFF, BECAUSE
THAT'S ALSO DELICIOUS.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE PART?
ALL OF IT.
FOLKS HERE
ARE OBSESSED WITH THEM,
AND THAT INCLUDES THE OWNERS.
YOU HAVE
A CRAB TATTOO.
FEMALE BLUE CRAB.
THEY ARE GOIN' HOT.
BILL GREEN
AND HIS WIFE MARY...
WE HAVE A TABLE
OF SEVEN COMING IN.
WORKED THE OPEN-AIR MARKET
WHEN THEY WERE KIDS.
WATCH YOUR STEP.
EIGHT YEARS AGO,
THEY OPENED THIS JOINT
NEAR STONEY CREEK
OFF CHESAPEAKE BAY,
SERVING EVERYTHING CRAB.
A POUND OF JUMBO LUMP CRABMEAT,
A HALF CRAB TOAST,
A CRAB PRETZEL
AND A CRAB BALL.
AND IN
THE MARYLAND TRADITION...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
STEAMED BY THE BASKET
WITH SWEET CORN
AND TOSSED ON THE TABLE.
I LOVE CRABS.
YEAH.
THESE ARE DELICIOUS.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO STEAM CRAB?
MY FATHER.
AND HE'S STILL DOIN' 'EM
DAD'S WAY.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR SEASONINGS TOGETHER
THAT WE'RE GONNA
SEASON THE CRABS WITH.
SALT--KOSHER SALT, PAPRIKA,
DRY MUSTARD.
CHILI FLAKE.
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
THERE WE GO.
A LITTLE THYME.
THYME.
SO NO OLD BAY ON THIS?
NO, NO OLD BAY
ON THE STEAMED CRAB.
EVERYBODY STOP
FOR A MOMENT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I--
THE WORLD AS I KNOW IT.
A LITTLE BIT
LIKE A BLACKENING SPICE.
(whistles)
CAYENNE'S FRESH.
THE STEAM IS GONNA PICK UP
THESE SEASONINGS AND FLAVORS
AND GO IN THROUGH THE CREVICES
AND JOINTS OF THE SHELL.
PLUS, IT'S GONNA BE ON THERE
WHEN YOU'RE PICKIN' 'EM.
YOU'RE GONNA GET IT ALL OVER
YOUR FINGERS WHEN YOU EAT 'EM.
OKAY, NOW WE GO OUT.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
WITH THEM?
YOU WANT TO LAYER THEM
DOWN IN HERE.
YOU SHOULD GET
A CRAB BELT BUCKLE.
CRAB BELT BUCKLE?
OR CRAB SHOULDER PADS,
CRAB WATCH.
AND THE SEASONING
WE MADE EARLIER.
YOU JUST GO THROUGH THAT
SEASONING LIKE CRAZY.
YEAH.
GET SOME FRESH CORN, PUT IT
RIGHT ON TOP OF THE CRAB.
NOW WE GO TO THE STEAM.
(whistles)
PUT A LID ON IT.
25 MINUTES.
CHECK.
THE CRABS ARE READY.
BRIGHT RED. WE PUT
THEM ON THE PLATTER,
AND THEN WE GO HAVE WHAT
WE CALL THE CRAB FEAST?
YEP.
IS THAT THE WAY
HE DOES IT EVERY TIME?
YES.
IT'S JUST FANTASTIC.
THEY'RE VERY RICH.
IT'S BUTTERY.
IT'S SWEET.
THE SALT COMPLEMENTS IT
REALLY WELL.
THE SEASONING ON THE CRAB
IS PRETTY OUTSTANDING. WOW.
HANG OUT LONG ENOUGH,
THEY'LL FEED YOU.
THAT'S CRAB ON A STICK.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
DELICIOUS.
ANY SPECIAL METHODS
OF CRAB EATING?
THERE'S DIFFERENT
WAYS TO DO IT.
WE TEACH OUR KIDS
WHEN THEY'RE YOUNG
HOW TO PICK A CRAB.
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME THIS
BACK IN SOUTH BALTIMORE
40 YEARS AGO.
I TAKE OUT ALL THE CLAWS
AND THE FINS FIRST.
SOME PEOPLE
WILL USE A KNIFE.
YOU USE IT TO CUT THE CRAB IN
HALF SO YOU CAN GET TO THIS.
THAT'S A WASTE OF TIME.
JUST CRUSH IT IN MY HANDS.
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I SMASH IT, REACH IN
AND GRAB IT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN
LITTLE SANTA'S WORKSHOP.
I'M MAKING CRAB
FOR SUSIE.
NOW DO YOU GUYS
KNOW THIS GAME--
THE BREAK-OFF, PEEL-OFF,
PICK-AND-DIG?
NEVER DID THAT.
HUH? HUH? HUH?
NOW DO YOU ONLY
EAT THEM WITH BUTTER?
THAT'S HOW I WAS RAISED.
YOU GET HORSERADISH. MMM.
VINEGAR.
THIS IS VINEGAR.
NOW IS THIS THE WAY
TO DO IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
I JUST LIKE
TO EAT MINE PLAIN.
I LIKE 'EM NAKED,
BUT A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE ON IT.
OHH.
YOU LIKE IT
WITH SOME VINEGAR?
THAT MIGHT JUST BE IT
FOR ME.
NOW HOW ELSE
DO THEY DO THE CRAB HERE?
THEY DO A FRIED HARD CRAB,
WHERE YOU PEEL THE BATTER
OFF AND EAT IT.
SERIOUSLY?
THAT'S CREAM OF CRAB?
YEAH. HEAVY ON THE CRAB.
THEY'RE EVEN STUFFING IT
IN SHRIMP.
TWO FOR YOU, ONE FOR ME?
I LIKE THE WAY YOU ROLL.
LOOK HOW BEAUTIFUL
THEY LOOK. WHOA.
MMM.
CRAB TOAST.
AND HOWEVER
THEY'RE SERVING THEM...
ORDER UP.
BILL AND MARRY ARE PROUD
TO BE CARRYING ON
THE OLD MARYLAND
CRAB SHACK TRADITION.
I HAVE A LOT
OF GREAT CUSTOMERS...
THAT KEEP COMING BACK
FOR THE CLASSIC FAVORITES
THAT THEY GREW UP WITH.
MMM.
AND FOR A LOT OF FOLKS
AROUND HERE...
HOW WAS EVERYTHING?
EXCELLENT.
THAT MEANS CRAB CAKES.
NO CLAW MEAT IN IT.
IT'S JUST PURE LUMP CRABMEAT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SAUCE
FOR OUR JUMBO LUMP CRAB CAKES.
NICE HEAVY MAYONNAISE.
OLD BAY.
OLD BAY, PREPARED MUSTARD,
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
WORCESTERSHIRE,
AND WE'LL WHIP IT UP TILL
IT INCORPORATES A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE LIQUID EGG.
THIS IS THE GLUE.
THIS IS THE BINDER.
YEAH.
NOW A LITTLE BAKING POWDER.
THAT'LL GIVE YOU
A LITTLE WHOOMP.
MM-HMM. IT'LL ALSO THICKEN
IT UP A LITTLE BIT MORE.
NOW HOW MANY CRAB CAKES
WILL THIS MAKE?
THIS WILL MAKE ABOUT 25.
WOW. SO THIS IS 5 POUNDS?
6 POUNDS.
MM-HMM. JUMBO LUMP.
I WAS OFF ON THIS HAND,
BECAUSE IT'S A NEW ARM BAND.
A LITTLE BIT OF BREADING--
REGULAR OLD WHITE BREAD.
NO CRUSTS.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT. YOU JUST WANT
ENOUGH TO HOLD IT TOGETHER.
THIS IS A BINDER, BABY.
THIS IS A CRAB CAKE,
NOT A BREAD CAKE.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING--
TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF PARSLEY.
STIR THAT UP
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
SO YOU'RE REALLY
EYEBALLIN' THIS.
SOMETIMES YOU'LL GET
24 1/2 CRAB CAKES.
SOMETIMES YOU'LL GET 25.
JUST LIVING ON THE EDGE.
SO NOW WE'RE JUST
GONNA FORM 'EM.
I'M PRETTY CLOSE--WITHIN 1/2
AN OUNCE MOST OF THE TIME.
REALLY?
WHAT SIZE WE GOIN' FOR?
WE'RE GOIN' FOR A 6 OUNCE.
AND PLATE 'EM.
AND THAT'S NOT GONNA
FALL APART?
IN THE OVEN, 350,
7 TO 10 MINUTES.
KEEP YOUR EYE ON IT.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YOUR WEAPON, SIR.
I CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO SEE
ANY FILLER.
HOLD ME.
MMM. SUPER FRESH.
MM-HMM.
I'M NOT GETTING OVER-CITRUS.
I'M NOT GETTING OVER-MUSTARD.
I'M NOT GETTING OVER-OLD BAY.
MM-HMM.
TASTING THE CRAB.
EVERYBODY'S WORKING
TOGETHER TO ENHANCE...
ENHANCE THAT JUMBO LUMP.
YEAH, WOW!
THE BEST PART ABOUT IT
IS THE AMOUNT OF CRABMEAT.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF CRAB IN IT.
I GET IT ALL THE TIME.
ANYTHING CRAB RELATED
IS VERY GOOD HERE.
I'VE BEEN TO OTHER PLACES,
AND CRAB JUST AIN'T THE SAME.
THERE'S NOTHING BETTER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S PERFECT.
AND YOUR FAVORITE PART
OF DOING THIS WHOLE THING?
WE'VE GOTTEN A LOT
OF GOOD FRIENDS.
ONCE YOU TRY THEM, WHETHER
YOU'RE FROM MARYLAND OR NOT,
YOU'RE HOOKED--
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY HOOKED.
MMM. THIS IS HOW
I LIKE TO EAT CRAB.
HANG OUT WITH A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
AND SAY I'VE NEVER HAD ANY
AND LET THEM DO THE PICKING.
WOW, I WONDER WHAT
COLD BEER TASTES LIKE.
UP NEXT...
HOMEMADE--
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GOOD.
WE'RE HEADING TO MEMPHIS
FOR THE SECRETS OF SOMETHING
CALLED CHOW-CHOW.
MMM.
IT'S A PICKLED CABBAGE
CONDIMENT.
I HAVE WANTED TO KNOW HOW
TO MAKE THIS FOR YEARS.
THAT'S GREAT.
WHEN YOU COME
TO MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE,
YOU GOT TO KNOW
ABOUT BEALE STREET,
BUT IF YOU MAKE
AN ACCIDENTAL TURN
AND FIND YOURSELF HERE
ON NORTH MAIN,
WELL, THEN YOU GOT
TO STOP AND COME OUT
AND CHECK OUT THIS
TASTY LITTLE JOINT--ALCENIA'S.
NOW I GOT TO GO IN HERE
AND MEET THE OWNER,
'CAUSE I HEAR
SHE KNOWS HOW TO CHA-CHA.
I CALL IT
"THE CHA-CHA-CHA,"
YOU KNOW, LIKE
YOU'RE DOING LIKE THIS.
IT'S SO GOOD.
I'VE ALWAYS CALLED
IT "CHOW-CHOW."
WHATEVER YOU CALL IT...
THAT SMELLS SO GOOD.
IT'S AN ALCENIA'S SPECIALTY
AND A SOUTHERN FAVORITE...
IT'S A PICKLED CABBAGE
CONDIMENT.
THIS IS THE TASTE
OF MEMPHIS.
AT A PLACE
FULL OF SOUTHERN TASTE.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
(woman) THEY'RE PERFECT.
LIKE A LITTLE
VEGETABLE DONUT.
I LOVE THE CORNBREAD.
IT'S SO GOOD.
FRIED PORK CHOP--
AS BIG AS MY HEAD.
MMM.
THREE CATFISH ON HERE.
LIKE GOING TO
SOMEBODY'S GRANDMOTHER'S
AFTER CHURCH ON SUNDAY.
CUT 'EM IN HALF.
THAT WOULD BE
GRANDMA BJ CHESTER-TAMAYO.
GOT YOUR BUTTER
AND EVERYTHING?
SHE PUTS THE LOVE
INTO IT.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S WHAT FOOD'S ABOUT.
IT'S ABOUT LOVE.
MWAH.
SHE COOKS A LOT OF DISHES
THAT REMIND US OF GROWING UP.
EVEN THOUGH...
I DIDN'T COOK
GROWING UP.
BUT HER MAMA ALCENIA DID.
I MADE MY FIRST POUND CAKE
AT 8 YEARS OLD.
MY MOM WAS SUCH A GREAT COOK.
I DIDN'T WANT TO LOSE THAT.
THEY'RE LOOKING GOOD.
SO 11 YEARS AGO,
BJ OPENED THIS JOINT.
IN HONOR OF MY MOM. NOTHING ELSE
IT COULD BE BUT THAT.
SHE HAD TO LEARN.
I CAME BACK AMD FORTH
AND GOT HER TO LEARN HOW.
IT'S READY.
OKAY. IT'S READY?
SHE DONE IT GOOD NOW.
AS GOOD
AS ANYONE'S GRANDMOTHER.
FROM CHICKEN AND WAFFLES...
IT'S VERY GOOD.
TO SWEET POTATO PIE...
I KNOW IT'S A DESSERT,
BUT I USUALLY EAT IT FIRST.
TO THE DISH SHE MIGHT
BE MOST FAMOUS FOR.
CHOW-CHOW...
I LIKE TO SAY CHA-CHA--
GIVE A LITTLE JAZZ TO IT.
WHICH IS FANTASTIC.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA
SALT THE CABBAGE?
ABOUT THREE HEADS
OF CABBAGE.
AND THE REASON WHY YOU'RE
PUTTING THE SALT ON IT--
TO SOFTEN THE CABBAGE.
RIGHT, IT'S GONNA
SWEAT IT A LITTLE BIT.
EXACTLY. MAKE IT TENDER.
IT'S GONNA DRAW OUT
SOME MOISTURE.
NOW HOW LONG IS THAT
GONNA SIT LIKE THAT?
TWO, TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA WASH IT.
THIS IN THE RINSED CABBAGE
THAT SAT WITH THE SALT
ON IT FOR TWO HOURS?
EXACTLY.
TAKE ABOUT 3 CUPS OF WATER,
4 CUPS OF VINEGAR.
THEN WE TAKE
PICKLING SPICE.
ABOUT 6 TABLESPOONS.
WHILE THIS IS BOILING,
WE GET OUR PEPPERS READY.
THIS IS THE JALAPEÑO HERE.
WE DO BOTH HOT AND MILD.
A LITTLE RED CHILI.
I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND PUT THE SUGAR FIRST.
LET IT DISSOLVE.
LET IT DISSOLVE, AND IT
DON'T MAKE ANY DIFFERENCE
WHICH PROCESS
YOU PUT THIS IN, GUY.
IT'S ALL GONNA GET
MIXED IN TOGETHER ANYWAY.
HERE, I'LL TRADE YOU.
OKAY, BABY. THANK YOU.
THERE YOU GO.
3 CUPS OF ONIONS.
MM-HMM.
THREE HEADS OF CABBAGE.
EXACTLY. THAT IN HERE.
AND THEN HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIT HERE
AND SIMMER
OR BOIL TOGETHER?
ABOUT TWO HOURS.
WOW. SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE REGULAR TOMATOES
AND THE GREEN TOMATOES.
RIGHT.
HOW LONG ARE THESE GONNA
GO AND COOK INSIDE THIS?
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
SO IT REALLY IS LIKE
A 5 HOUR PROCESS.
BUT LOOK AT THOSE PEPPERS,
THE ONIONS,
THE CABBAGE COOKING DOWN.
YOU KNOW WHAT? I HAVE WANTED TO
KNOW HOW TO MAKE THIS FOR YEARS.
(utensil clangs on ground)
MMM. DON'T ANYBODY
TOUCH THAT.
IT'S HOT NOW.
MMM.
IT'S REALLY TASTY.
GOOD TEXTURE.
OKAY.
SO YOU EAT IT COLD
ON TOP OF SOMETHING HOT.
RIGHT. EXACTLY.
NICE SWEET AND SOUR. I KNEW I
WAS GONNA COME IN AND CHA-CHA.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT'S WHAT
I WAS GONNA GET. THAT'S GREAT.
YOUR MAMA TAUGHT YOU GOOD
ON THAT ONE.
THANK YOU.
I ESPECIALLY LIKE
THE CHOICE OF SPICES.
VERY GOOD--
SWEET BUT SPICY.
HOMEMADE--
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GOOD.
A COUPLE WARM.
OLD-FASHIONED STUFF
IS MY MOM.
OKAY.
FROM SWEET POTATOES
AND COLLARD GREENS...
IT'S GREAT.
I LOVE THE VEGETABLES.
AND NUT-ENCRUSTED
BREAD PUDDING...
SOME OF THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
HER DESSERTS ARE INCREDIBLE.
TO THIS FAMILY FAVORITE.
APPLE BUTTER.
OH, I GOT YOU.
HERE'S SOME APPLE BUTTER.
MMM.
REALLY FLAVORFUL APPLESAUCE--
A LOT OF CINNAMON IN THERE.
LOOK AT THIS CATFISH.
SHE'S PUTTING IT ALL TOGETHER
IN A TRADITIONAL SOUTHERN WAY.
THANK YOU, BILL,
SO MUCH, BABY.
WE GIVE YOU ONE MEAT,
TWO SIDES, GRITS AND RICE...
(Guy) GRITS AND RICE.
AND YOUR DRINK.
TODAY, I HAD
THE FRIED CHICKEN
WITH GREEN BEANS
AND THE SPECIAL CORN.
(woman) I LOVE
THEIR CATFISH.
IT'S KIND OF SPICY,
REALLY CRUNCHY. I LOVE IT.
FRIED PORK CHOP.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU THE BEST
PORK CHOPS YOU EVER HAD.
OKAY, SO A LITTLE BIT OF
SEASONING GOES INTO YOUR WASH.
RIGHT. WE GONNA
TAKE THE FLOUR.
I'M GONNA ADD ALL THESE
DIFFERENT SEASONINGS,
AND I JUST SHAKE IT
AROUND THERE.
NOW WE NEED TO GET
THE BEST PART.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THIS?
I LIKE THAT ONE.
OKAY.
DO YOU TAKE THE WHOLE TRAY
OF PORK OUT THERE
AND LET PEOPLE PICK?
NO, JUST ONLY YOU,
'CAUSE YOU SO SPECIAL.
THROW A LITTLE TENDERIZE
ON IT.
RIGHT.
SHE PUT IT IN THE WASH, AND THEN
IT GOES INTO THE DREDGE.
THEN WHAT WE DO IS TAKE IT.
AND THEN IT GOES TO
A BIG HOT TUB BUFFET.
WOW.
IT'S HOT NOW.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT CRUNCH.
IT'S NOT OVERCOOKED.
THE BREADING STICKS NICE.
I THINK I COULD USE A LITTLE
OF THAT APPLE BUTTER SAUCE.
MMM. THAT APPLE BUTTER
IS ON POINT.
I COULD EAT
THE WHOLE PIG.
BUT YOU STILL GOT
TO PICK YOUR SIDES.
GREEN BEANS.
IT'S TOUGH TO MAKE A DECISION,
'CAUSE EVERYTHING
SHE HAS IS SO GOOD.
HER VEGGIES
ARE VERY TASTY.
THE CORN IS VERY SPICY.
FRIED GREEN TOMATO--
THEY'RE VERY GOOD.
HERE IN MEMPHIS, IT'S LIKE
A MAJOR FOOD GROUP.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
AND ANOTHER LOCAL FAVORITE--
HOT WATER CORNBREAD.
I NEVER HEARD OF CORNBREAD
MADE WITH HOT WATER.
I ATE IT FIRST.
I'M SAD IT'S GONE.
WE'RE GONNA USE
SELF-RISING MEAL.
THIS IS CORNMEAL?
MM-HMM. WE'RE GONNA PUT
2 CUPS OF SUGAR.
THE KEY TO THIS
IS HOT WATER.
CAN YOU STIR THAT
FOR ME, BABY?
YOU GOT IT.
SEE IT KIND OF RISING
A LITTLE BIT?
YEAH, I SEE THAT.
THE HEAT'S ACTIVATING IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S ALMOST,
LIKE, DOUBLED IN VOLUME.
USE AN ICE CREAM SCOOP.
OKAY.
KIND LOOK LIKE A LARGE
50 CENT PIECE.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
THE BREAD FOR THE MEAL?
EXACTLY.
IT ALMOST LOOKS LIKE A LITTLE
BIT OF A CORNMEAL PANCAKE.
EXACTLY.
THAT ONE HAS MY NAME
ON IT RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT THERE. OKAY.
MMM. IT'S ALMOST CARAMELIZED.
WOW, THAT'S SWEET.
GOOD CRUNCH,
GOOD TEXTURE TO IT.
YEAH.
I LIKE IT. I'M GONNA
REMEMBER THAT ONE.
THIS IS THE DEFINITION
OF HOT WATER CORNBREAD.
I LOVE THAT
IT'S HOME COOKING.
BJ ENJOYS COOKING.
WITH OUR HOMEMADE
PRESERVES.
IT'S ALWAYS A GREAT HOT MEAL.
THIS IS SOUL FOOD.
SOUL FOOD'S MEANT TO BE SHARED.
IT RAISED US ALL TOGETHER.
I WANT THEM TO HAVE
THE SAME EXPERIENCE
THAT THEY HAD AT THEIR MOM
AND GRANDMOM HOUSE.
THAT'S WHAT ALCENIA'S
IS ABOUT.
KEEPING FAMILY
TRADITIONS ALIVE...
I WAS 10 YEARS OLD WHEN
I STARTED MAKING BISCUITS.
AND PASSING THEM ON.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
ALCENIA.
ALCENIA. OH, IS THIS
YOUR RESTAURANT?
YES.
VERY NICE. SEE?
SHE'S JUST LIKE--
JUST LIKE HER GRANDMA.
YOU GET TWO VEGETABLES.
AND ALL YOU BRING IN
IS LOVE, MAMA'S RECIPE
AND A GOOD WORK ETHIC,
AND LOOK AT YOU 11 YEARS LATER.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THAT'S A BIG DEAL, GIRL.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
EXCELLENT.
UP NEXT...
EVERY BIT OF IT'S HOMEMADE.
MINNESOTA.
MOSTACCIOLI.
MMM.
FOR RED SAUCE, MEATBALLS...
AND SOMETHING CALLED
SPAGHETTI PIE.
DYNAMITE, MAN.
ON TRIPLE "D," WE HIT
ALL KIND OF JOINTS.
NOW ONE OF MY FAVORITES
IS ITALIAN.
THERE'S ITALIAN,
AND THEN THERE'S ITALIAN--
YOU KNOW, THE PLACES THAT
ARE MAKING THEIR OWN MEATBALLS,
THEIR DOUGH, THEIR FRESH PASTA,
THEIR SAUCES.
NOW THE FOLKS NORTH OF THE TWIN
CITIES, WELL, THEY'RE ON POINT,
'CAUSE THEY GET
TO EXPERIENCE THAT EVERY DAY
HERE AT THIS PLACE--
DONATELLI'S.
(woman) RIGATONI SPECIAL
FOR HERE.
EVERY BIT OF IT'S HOMEMADE.
MEAT AND CHEESE.
IT DOESN'T GET
ANY BETTER THAN THAT.
MOSTACCIOLI.
MMM. WINNER, WINNER,
MOSTACCIOLI DINNER.
THIS IS COMFORT FOOD RIGHT HERE.
MEATBALL SANDWICH.
HOMEMADE MEATBALLS,
HOMEMADE RED SAUCE.
THE FOOD'S AWESOME.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
CLASSIC RECIPES
STEVE DONATELLE'S CREW
HAS BEEN CRANKING OUT
IN A MINNESOTA STRIP MALL...
(woman) RIGATONI
MEATBALL.
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
THANKS, GUYS.
HOME-COOKING FOOD.
(Steve) MY DAD IS ITALIAN.
MY DAD'S SISTER LIVED
RIGHT NEXT DOOR TO US.
THE MOST WONDERFUL COOK
YOU'D EVER WANT TO MEET.
PESTO CREAM SAUCE.
IT LOOKS GREAT.
BASICALLY, I LEARNED HOW
GOOD FOOD IS SUPPOSED TO TASTE.
MMM. IT'S GREAT.
AND HOW IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE MADE...
MORE CHEESE OVER HERE.
FROM SCRATCH...
MAKES US DIFFERENT
FROM EVERYBODY ELSE.
EVEN THE PASTA.
SEE, THIS IS WHEN
YOU KNOW IT'S LEGIT.
HEAD COOK AARON LIEDL'S
SCRATCH-MAKING
EIGHT DIFFERENT KINDS.
THE PASTA'S MADE FRESH HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR DURUM FLOUR.
THEN WE ADD OUR SEMOLINA.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
LET IT MIX FOR A MINUTE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR EGGS,
A LITTLE WARM WATER.
NOW IT'S GONNA COME OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE MEDUSA
THE PASTA MACHINE.
TWO MOSTACCIOLIS.
AND THEY'RE TOPPING
THE HOMEMADE PASTA
WITH ALL KINDS
OF HOMEMADE SAUCE,
FROM CREAMY ALFREDO
TO THIS ALL-TIME CLASSIC.
I COME HERE
FOR THE SPECIAL RED SAUCE.
YOU CAN REALLY TELL
THAT THEY MAKE IT HERE.
AND IT'S MADE
EVERY MORNING?
EVERY MORNING.
SIX CANS OF TOMATO PASTE.
NOW AFTER ALL THAT,
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR PURéE.
TOMATO FILLETS.
TOMATO FILLETS?
IT'S SLICED UP TOMATO,
AND THEN WE GRIND IT ALL UP.
THIS LOOKS LIKE
A SPLASHING OPPORTUNITY.
OH, YEAH.
GET IN CLOSE.
YEAH. YEAH, YEAH.
TWO CANS OF TOMATO JUICE,
CHICKEN AND BEEF BASE,
PARMESAN CHEESE,
GARLIC SALT,
BLACK PEPPER,
BASIL AND PARSLEY.
SAUTéED ONIONS IN OIL
AND OUR WATER.
A LOT OF WATER.
WE USUALLY LET IT SIMMER
ABOUT 8 HOURS A DAY.
SMELLS PRETTY FANTASTIC.
BUT THE MEAT
DOESN'T GO IN THIS?
NOPE, WE TAKE THIS OUT
AND PUT IT IN THE MEAT.
SO LET'S GO MAKE THE MEAT.
THEN WE'LL PUT THAT
IN THERE?
YEP.
SO WE JUST DUMP OUR GROUND
BEEF ON AND BREAK IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR GARLIC
AND OUR STEAK SEASONING.
SO WE SCOOP IT UP,
PUT IT IN THERE,
ADD THE SAUCE, AND THEN
THAT'S READY TO BE SERVED
ON TOP OF THE MOSTACCIOLI.
YEP.
ADD A LITTLE CHEDDAR,
A LITTLE MOZZARELLA,
AND MIX IT ALL UP.
TOP IT OFF WITH
MORE MEAT SAUCE HERE.
WHAT IS THAT OVER THERE?
(laughs)
WHAT?
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
THEN WE PUT
THE MOZZARELLA ON
AND SOME CHEDDAR.
WHY DON'T WE ADD
SOME CHEESE TO IT?
AND THEN WE PUT IT IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
WOW.
YEAH, TOSS A LITTLE
PARMESAN ON THERE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THIS COULD
POSSIBLY HAVE MORE CHEESE.
MMM. REALLY GOOD.
THE SAUCE IS REALLY NICE.
FRESH MADE PASTA--
SO NICE AND LIGHT
AND GREAT TEXTURE TO IT.
THAT'S THE MONEY
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S IS THE MONEY.
ACTUALLY,
THAT'S THE MOSTACCIOLI.
YEAH.
BAKED MOSTACCIOLI
MEAT SAUCE.
VERY REAL TASTING--
THAT'S WHY I LIKE TO GET IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD
HAS BEEN REALLY GOOD.
JUST BEEN A GOOD FAMILY
RESTAURANT FOR A LOT OF YEARS.
STEVE SAYS WHAT
HE'S DOING HERE...
BAKED RIGATONI.
IS THE FOOD
HE GREW UP WITH...
THE SAUCE
HAS REALLY GREAT FLAVOR.
FROM WHAT HE CALLS
ITALIAN-AMERICAN CLASSICS...
SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALL.
TO A PASTA, EGG, VEGGIE
AND CHEESE THING
THEY'RE CALLING SPAGHETTI PIE.
THIS SHOULD BE CALLED
DONATELLI'S HOUSE
OF ALL TYPES OF CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT
CREAMY GOODNESS.
MMM.
WOW, THAT IS RICH.
YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES THAT?
THAT GREEN BELL PEPPER.
YEAH.
I MEAN, IT'S SUPER CREAMY.
IT'S SUPER CHEESY.
THE TOMATO SAUCE, YOU KNOW,
IS JUST A PERFECT BALANCE.
DYNAMITE, MAN.
REALLY GOOD.
GOOD.
AND YOU'RE HAVING
SPAGHETTI PIE?
YEAH. IT'S GOOD.
STILL, MOST FOLKS ARE PACKING
IN FOR THE CLASSICS.
THE BAKED LASAGNA--
ONE OF THEIR HOUSE SPECIALTIES.
I'VE GOT THE MEATBALL SANDWICH.
MADE WITH
THEIR HOMEMADE MEATBALLS--
ABSOLUTELY INCREDIBLE.
WE'RE MAKING MEATBALLS.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA START
OUT WITH OUR HAMBURGER.
GROUND PORK?
YEP. EGGS,
WATER.
NOW IS THIS BREADCRUMBS
YOU GUYS HAVE MADE
FROM LEFTOVER BREAD?
WE MADE THESE. YEP.
NICE.
WE GOT PARSLEY, BASIL,
BLACK PEPPER, GARLIC SALT,
ONION SALT AND SALT.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
AND THEN WE CLOSE HER UP.
SET A TIMER FOR SIX MINUTES.
IT'LL BE PERFECT.
THOSE THAT ARE JUST TUNING IN,
WE'RE NOT MAKING A CAKE.
THAT'S ACTUALLY A MEATBALL.
YOU GONNA GET IN ON THIS?
I HAVE BLING RIP-AGE.
OKAY.
YOU READY?
ALL RIGHT. DON'T BE AFRAID
TO GET IN THERE.
NOW IS ANYTHING GONNA GO
ON TOP OF THESE BAD BOYS?
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA COVER THEM
IN WATER SO THEY DON'T BURN.
IN THE BIG
CONVECTION OVEN. WOW.
THERE THEY ARE.
EENY, MEENY, MINY...
HEY, MOE.
MMM. NICE FLAVOR.
NOT TOO DENSE.
NOT TOO LOOSE. NOW IT'S TIME
FOR A MEATBALL SANDWICH.
NICE ITALIAN BREAD.
YOU GUYS HAVE A BAKERY
THAT MAKES THIS?
YES, WE DO.
A LITTLE MOZZ.
MOZZARELLA CHEESE AND OUR
TRADITIONAL RED SAUCE.
GET THAT MEATBALL ON THERE.
THEN WE ADD OUR SAUCE.
NOW WE GOT TO GET
THAT MOZZARELLA ON THERE,
AND THEN WE COOK IT
IN THE OVEN.
(whistles)
ALL RIGHT, THERE SHE IS.
MAN.
SO THE MEATBALL IS STILL
NICE AND SUPER JUICY.
MMM. WELL, YOU'RE NOT
SKIMPING ON THE CHEESE.
NO.
WE NEVER SKIMP
ON THE CHEESE.
MNH-MNH.
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
THAT'S LIKE EIGHT BUCKS.
COME ON DOWN TO DONATELLI'S
AND FEED YOUR FAMILY OF FOUR
FOR EIGHT BUCKS.
GREAT SANDWICH.
GREAT JOB, MAN.
OH, YOU GOT TO BLOW IT UP
AT THE END.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING
THAT'S GREAT AT DONATELLI'S.
CHEESE IS THE KICKER HERE
FOR EVERYTHING.
AND THAT INCLUDES PIZZA
WITH EVERYTHING
WHEN WE COME BACK.
HOLY MOLY. MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
EXCELLENT.
STEVE DONATELLE'S CREW
HAS BEEN CRANKING OUT
FAMILY FAVORITES...
HERE'S YOUR SPAGHETTI PIE.
NORTHEAST OF
ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA...
THERE YOU GO.
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS NOW.
(Aaron) MOSTACCIOLI.
THE MOSTACCIOLI
IS VERY GOOD.
JUST ONE OF EIGHT PASTAS
THEY'RE MAKING FROM SCRATCH...
MMM.
LIKE ALMOST EVERYTHING HERE.
NOTHING MATCHES
THIS PIZZA HERE.
PEPPERONI MUSHROOM.
NOW HOW MANY PIZZAS
DO YOU GUYS SERVE IN A DAY?
HUNDREDS.
AND JESSICA KISSLE'S BEEN
MAKING THE DOUGH FOR 10 YEARS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE THREE
BIG BINS OF DOUGH ON HAND.
AS DO I OFTEN.
AND THEY'RE TOPPING IT
WITH EVERYTHING,
FROM A DEEP-DISH VEGGIE
TO THIS MONSTER.
HEART STOPPER PIZZA.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
IT'S A REAL MEATY
AND LOADED-UP PIZZA--FANTASTIC.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE HEART STOPPER PIZZA.
DOUGH'S OVER HERE.
I HAVE A HOPPER LIKE THIS
AT JOHNNY GARLIC'S,
BUT THIS MUST
GET JUST WORKED.
OH, IT DOES.
HOW MANY TIMES IS IT
SUPPOSED TO GO THROUGH?
ABOUT THREE TIMES
IS WHAT I USUALLY DO,
AND I JUST KIND OF FLIP IT
AROUND A LITTLE BIT.
SO LOOK AT HOW NICE
AND THIN THAT IS.
GOT TO CUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
THAT HAS DONE SOME TIME.
YOU WANT TO SEE
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE
TO GO THROUGH THE PIZZA
CAR WASH IN FLAVOR TOWN?
WHOOP, WHOOP,
WHOOP, WHOOP, WHOOP.
THEN YOU TAKE YOUR SAUCE.
MADE FRESH THEIR WAY.
WHY NOT JUST USE A SPOON?
DOESN'T REALLY MIX AS WELL
AS WHEN YOU USE YOUR HAND.
THAT'S SOME
GOOD-LOOKING SAUCE.
WE GOT TO GRAB
OUR TOPPINGS.
SO I ALWAYS START
WITH THE SAUSAGE.
OH, WE HAVE ALL
OF THE MEAT GROUPS.
OH, YEAH. HAMBURGER'S NEXT.
SOME PEPPERONI.
THEN THE HAM GOES ON NEXT,
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT YOUR BACON.
OF COURSE.
14 PIECES OF BACON,
SIX PIECES OF HAM,
2 HANDFULS OF PEPPERONI,
TWO SOFTBALLS OF SAUSAGE
AND HAMBURGER
ON TOP A LITTLE
TINY THIN CRUST.
YES.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO NOW?
TWO WHEELBARROWS
OF CHEESE? THERE YOU GO.
LOAD IT UP WITH CHEESE--
TWO WHEELBARROWS.
550?
550.
HOLY MOLY.
BRING IT ON OVER HERE.
WHOA.
YOU LIKE THE KNIFE?
(Australian accent) THAT'S NOT
A KNIFE. THAT'S A KNIFE.
(normal voice) WHERE
DOES ONE FIND SUCH--
I MEAN, DO YOU GO
TO PIRATES "R" US?
YEAH, WE DO.
IT'S HOT.
IT IS HOT.
MMM. GOT A NICE
CRUNCH TO IT.
SEE HOW THIN THAT IS?
THERE'S ENOUGH CHEESE
TO SINK THE TITANIC.
THE SAUSAGE--I MEAN, REALLY,
THIS IS A DELICIOUS PIZZA.
MMM. WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S THE BEST PIZZA
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
YOU CAN TELL IT'S MADE BY PEOPLE
WHO LIKE DOING WHAT THEY DO.
I STILL LIKE COMING TO WORK,
BECAUSE I LIKE THE PEOPLE
THAT I WORK WITH.
I LOVE MY CUSTOMERS.
ONE OF OUR REGULARS.
I LOVE IT HERE.
NICE JOB, MAN.
REALLY NICE JOB. COOL PLACE.
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
UM, JUST THE ONE GLOVE.
CAN YOU--JUST FOR A SECOND,
CAN YOU GIVE ME
A LITTLE "HOO."
HEE-HEE.
THAT'S GOOD.
YEAH.