WHAT'S UP, EVERYBODY?
I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS IS
THE PLACE TO GO.
THIS TRIP...
FIRST COURSE--SALADS,
SECOND COURSE--CHOP.
AND WHO WROTE TO ME?
WE BOTH DID.
DINERS YOU SENT ME TO...
VERY UNIQUE.
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
IT IS A DINER/
KIND OF GOURMET.
YOU GUYS GOT
A SPRING ROLL WORKIN'?
DINER COOKIN'
DONE HIS WAY...
OH, BABY. CLASSIC DINER
FOOD SPUN UP WITH MODERN TWISTS.
EVEN FLAVORING BOURBON
WITH BACON FAT.
IT'S JUST A WHOLE BUNCH
OF SMOKY GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
AS CLASSIC
AS THEY COME IN BALTIMORE...
THERE YOU GO.
WITH A BIG MENU...
THEY HAVE EVERYTHING
YOU COULD PRETTY MUCH THINK OF.
FROM EVERYWHERE.
PORK CHOPS ROMANO,
CHICKEN CREOLE, VEAL PARMESAN.
THE BUS TO FLAVOR TOWN
JUST STOPPED OFF
AT THE BROADWAY DINER.
AND IN SALT LAKE CITY...
IT'S JUST A CLASSIC
AMERICAN DINER.
CORNED BEEF HASH?
WHERE THE HASH
IS HOMEMADE...
IT'S AWESOME.
YOU NEED
TO COME GET THIS.
AND THE SALMON'S
FRESH SMOKED.
WHY WE COME HERE
IS FOR THE SALMON.
I WANT TO BE YOU FOR
A MINUTE. MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
BOY, DID THE E-MAILS
COME ROLLING IN
ABOUT THIS DINER YOU WANT ME
TO CHECK OUT IN MINNEAPOLIS.
NOW IT OPENED IN THE '40s,
AND THE TOWN TALK, WELL, IT
LOOKS AS CLASSIC AS THEY COME,
BUT IT'S OWNED BY A CHEF
THAT CUT HIS TEETH
IN NEW YORK AND PARIS.
HE SAID HE CAME HERE TO DO WHAT
HE CALLS GOURMET COMFORT FOOD.
TWO SPECIALS.
NOT YOUR TYPICAL
DINER FOOD.
ARE THERE OTHER PLACES LIKE
THIS, OR IS THIS ONE OF A KIND?
VERY UNIQUE.
BUTTER WITH BACON--
YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
IT IS A DINER/
KIND OF GOURMET...
YOU GUYS GOT
A SPRING ROLL WORKING?
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
EXCELLENT DINER CLASSICS
LIKE BURGER AND FRIES.
BUT YOU CAN ALWAYS
TRY SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
EVERYONE CAN FIND
SOMETHING THEY WANT.
A DINER WITH FOOD THAT YOU WOULD
EXPECT TO FIND IN NEW YORK CITY.
OH, BABY.
WHICH IS WHERE CHEF AND OWNER
TOR WESTGARD USED TO WORK.
TWO MEAT SPECIALS.
AFTER COOKING IN ONE
OF NEW YORK'S TOP RESTAURANTS,
HE CAME BACK TO MINNESOTA
TO TRY SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
CLASSIC DINER FOOD
SPUN UP WITH MODERN TWISTS.
GO 2 MINUTES ON 35.
IT CAUGHT ON IN A HURRY
WITH A REGULAR CROWD
THAT KEEPS GROWING,
KEEPS COMING BACK
AND KEEPS SPREADING THE WORD.
WHAT'S UP WITH SENDING ME
THOSE RANDOM E-MAILS
THAT I GOTTA COME
CHECK THIS JOINT OUT?
BECAUSE IT'S
A GREAT PLACE.
THE ENVIRONMENT IS ALWAYS
AWESOME, THE BARTENDER,
THE OWNERS.
AND OF COURSE, THE FOOD.
TODAY, IT'S LAMB SHANK.
WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THE SHANK?
OH, IT'S DELICIOUS,
VERY TENDER, VERY GREAT.
THE ROOT VEGETABLES THAT
GO WITH IT--VERY AWESOME.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
A LITTLE BEAUTIFUL LAMB SHANK.
YOU GET THAT BIG
OLD BONE ON THE PLATE--
IT'S REALLY IMPRESSIVE
TO THE GUESTS.
THEY REALLY GET
A KICK OUT OF THAT.
KOSHER SALT, FRESH CRACKED BLACK
PEPPER, SEASON 'EM UP REAL WELL.
THIS IS
MY WAY TO PARTY.
THROW THEM
IN THE HOT OIL THERE.
WHEN YOU'RE PUTTING SIX OF THESE
DOWN, YOU BETTER BE SUPER HOT.
THESE ARE GETTING A NICE
LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM.
YEAH, GET A NICE, GOOD,
DEEP BROWN SEAR ON ALL SIDES.
NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
THE CANNED ORGANIC TOMATO.
THEN WE GOT SLICED GINGER,
GROUND TOASTED CORIANDER,
GROUND TOASTED CUMIN,
TOASTED WHOLE FENNEL SEEDS,
CINNAMON STICKS,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
FRESH CRACKED BLACK PEPPER...
I LIKE IT.
KOSHER SALT, A LITTLE BIT
OF TOMATO PASTE,
CARROTS AND ONIONS AND ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON ZEST.
HOLY MOLY. CHICKEN STOCK?
YEP.
WE'RE GONNA TURN IT UP A LITTLE
BIT. BRING IT TO SIMMER.
POP HER IN THE OVEN,
LET HER GO, SLOW AND LOW.
TAKE A WHIFF OF THAT...
(whistles)
ALL THE FLAVORS THAT
HAVE BEEN DEVELOPING.
THAT LOOKS
FANTASTIC. MMM.
SOME OF THOSE SMOKED TOMATO
GRITS, THIS BAD BOY,
ROASTED CARROTS AND PARSNIPS.
WE'RE GONNA FINISH WITH
CHIVES. THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
MMM.
THAT'S ABOUT THE MOST TENDER
YOU COULD EVER EXPECT.
MMM. FANTASTIC.
DELICIOUS, AND THOSE
GRITS... MMM.
YOU KNOW, IT'S LIKE A CLASSIC
DINER DISH JUST SPUN UPWARDS.
TWO CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
AND HE'S TREATING THIS SOUTHERN
CLASSIC THE SAME WAY.
HAVE YOU EVER
HAD 'EM BEFORE?
NO.
NEVER PREPARED LIKE THIS.
NO. IT'S GOOD.
WE DO IT WITH
A SOUR CHERRY ROSEMARY GRAVY
WITH A PULLED CHICKEN,
AND WE DO A WILD RICE WAFFLE.
SO WHEN PEOPLE
COME FROM THE SOUTH
AND THEY ORDER
CHICKEN AND WAFFLES,
AND THEY'RE EXPECTING FRIED
AND THEY GET THIS, ARE THEY
GONNA BE A LITTLE SURPRISED?
THAT'S EXCELLENT, MAN.
REALLY TASTY.
(man) GO WITH A MEAT
AND A FISH.
NOW WHATEVER'S COMING OUT
OF THE KITCHEN,
THIS PLACE IS DOING
WHAT DINERS HAVE ALWAYS DONE--
GIVING THE LOCALS A GO-TO PLACE
THEY CAN COUNT ON
FOR ANYTHING FROM
FRIED PICKLES TO PORK CHOPS
TO STEAK SALAD
AND ALL KINDS OF TWISTS.
FOR EXAMPLE,
THIS BRAT BURGER--IT'S GREAT.
IT'S EFFECTIVELY A BRAT
ON A BUN,
BUT THERE'S SPICY SAUERKRAUT.
HERE WE'VE GOT JUST
DICED UP PORK SHOULDER.
WE'VE GOT SOME
FATBACK, KOSHER SALT,
AND THIS IS A BRAT SPICE.
THIS IS GROUND WHITE PEPPER,
RUB SAGE,
GROUND CELERY SEED
AND GROUND MACE.
YOU DON'T SEE MACE
GETTING USED OFTEN.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT MILDER
THAN NUTMEG AND...
'CAUSE NUTMEG CAN BE...
AND IT'S JUST THE TRADITIONAL
GERMAN INGREDIENT IN BRATWURST.
LOAD HER UP.
WHOOPS-A-DAISY.
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S DEAD?
WE GOT OUR
BRAT BURGER MIX.
WE'RE JUST GONNA MAKE
ABOUT AN 8-OUNCE PATTY,
THROW HER DOWN.
A COUPLE SLICES
OF GRUYERE CHEESE,
A LITTLE BIT OF CRISPY BACON,
AND RIGHT TO THE BUN.
LOOK AT THAT.
FINISH IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT SPICY KRAUT.
TOR'S OWN COMBO OF BACON,
ONIONS, SPICES,
WHITE WINE AND SAUERKRAUT.
WE'LL MIX IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THE THAI CHILI GARLIC PASTE
TO JUST GIVE IT
A NICE SPICINESS.
SEE ANY SIMILARITY?
HUH. OH, MAN.
A LOT OF LOVE
WENT INTO THAT BURGER.
I MIGHT HAVE TO GET BACK TO YOU
ON THE WORDS I WANT TO USE.
IT EXCEEDED MY VOCABULARY.
THE TEXTURE'S FANTASTIC.
THE KICKER ON THAT,
UNQUESTIONABLY, IS
THAT SPICY SAUERKRAUT.
DUDE, I GOTTA
TELL YA, WELL DONE.
THANKS. WE TRY.
YOU DON'T TRY. YOU DO.
YOU SUCCEED. MMM.
HAVE YOU GUYS
HAD THIS?
IT IS DELICIOUS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
AND DOWN THE SIDE
AND UNDER YOUR CHIN,
IN YOUR GOATEE
AND DOWN YOUR FOREARMS.
IT'S FAIRLY SPICY
AND IT WAS REALLY GOOD.
(man) I'M GOING WITH
A MEAT AND A FISH.
IT'S ABOVE AND BEYOND
WHAT YOU CAN GET SOMEWHERE ELSE
THAT IS A TYPICAL DINER.
LARGE STEAK, NO CILANTRO.
WE HAVE TO CALL THIS, LIKE,
GOURMET ALL THE WAY.
YEAH.
ALL THE WAY TO THE BAR...
TRY IT. IT'S GONNA GO REALLY
GOOD WITH YOUR LAMB SHANK.
WHERE THE DRINKS
ARE AS WILD AS THE FOOD.
BACON-INFUSED BOURBON.
YES.
THIS IS A BEAKER
OF BACON FAT.
YEAH, ABOUT 3 OUNCES.
YOU DARE ME?
WE'RE JUST GONNA
DUMP THIS IN HERE,
AND IT'LL SLOWLY COOL DOWN,
AND IT'LL RISE TO THE TOP,
AND YOU LET IT SIT
FOR ABOUT SIX TO EIGHT HOURS.
AND THEN WHAT WE'LL DO
IS WE'LL PUT IT IN AN ICE BATH,
AND ALL THAT FAT
WILL COME TOGETHER...
AND THEN YOU
SCOOP IT OFF,
AND ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS STRAIN IT OFF.
THAT'S JUST A WHOLE BUNCH
OF SMOKEY GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
WOW.
I REALLY LIKE THE FEEL
OF THE RESTAURANT
AND THE PEOPLE
THAT WORK HERE.
I LOVE THE FOOD
BECAUSE THEY TAKE SIMPLE THINGS,
AND THEY MAKE IT BETTER.
I THINK THAT'S THE NICE PART
ABOUT IT, YOU KNOW--
THERE'S SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
(man) HERE'S THE BURGER. THERE'S
THE FISH, BUTTERED NOODLE.
FIRST COURSE--SALAD,
SECOND COURSE--CHOP.
IT'S A STEP-UP
DINER FOOD.
(woman) THE ENVIRONMENT
IS ALWAYS AWESOME.
ESPECIALLY, LIKE,
THE PBR IN THE KOOZIE.
TO HAVE A PLACE
THAT'S VERY COMFORTABLE...
ANYTHING ELSE
I CAN BRING YOU?
AND ALSO YOU CAN COUNT ON
GETTING REALLY GOOD FOOD
IS PRETTY RARE.
USING GREAT FOOD, COOKING
IT THE RIGHT WAY--FANTASTIC.
THAT WRAPPED TO GO,
PLATE, FORK AND ALL?
SURE. NOT A PROBLEM.
UP NEXT...
PORK CHOPS ROMANO,
CHICKEN CREOLE, VEAL PARMESAN.
WE'RE HEADING TO BALTIMORE...
FOR ME, COMING HERE
IS A SLICE OF AMERICA.
FOR COOKING WITH STYLE.
LIKE A MAGIC SHOW.
SO THIS LEG OF THE TRIP--
YOU WROTE IN
AND SENT ME TO BALTIMORE
TO THE KIND OF PLACES WE LOVE
DOING ON TRIPLE D--
A BIG, SHINY FAMILY-OWNED DINER
SERVING HOMEMADE EVERYTHING
FROM EVERYWHERE.
HEY, WELCOME
TO THE BROADWAY DINER.
PORK CHOPS ROMANO,
CHICKEN CREOLE, VEAL PARMESAN.
CHEESEBURGER...
SALAD WITH SWORDFISH.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
PUTTANESCA, MEAT LOAF.
SHRIMP CREOLE--NOT TOO SPICY.
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
OH, YEAH,
THAT LOOKS EXCELLENT.
YEAH.
WHAT IS THAT?
OPEN HOT BEEF SANDWICH
WITH FRENCH FRIES AND GRAVY.
JUST ONE OF THE REASONS
JONATHAN GORBACH
E-MAILED TO TELL ME
I GOTTA CHECK THIS PLACE OUT
AND SEE WHY
HIS WHOLE FAMILY LOVES IT...
GIVE ME
SOME KNUCKLES. POW.
THIS IS
THE PLACE TO GO.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU FEEL
LIKE THEY'RE FAMILY.
WITH GOOD REASON.
EVERYBODY GOOD?
EVERYBODY'S GOOD.
EVERYBODY GOOD.
AHH, TURKEY, PLEASE.
OWNER GEORGE KAVOURAKIS...
GIVE ME THAT TURKEY
OVER THERE.
RUNS THE PLACE
WITH HIS DAUGHTER...
THANK YOU.
AND NEPHEW...
CHEESE OMELET.
AND WANTS EVERYONE
ELSE TO FEEL...
OH, MY GOODNESS.
RIGHT AT HOME.
THANK YOU.
THEY HAVE EVERYTHING
YOU COULD THINK OF.
WE GOT NICE FRESH LOBSTER.
WE GOT SOME WONDERFUL MUSSELS.
A FEAST FIT FOR A KING
IS WHAT I'D CALL IT.
BUT GEORGE CALLS IT...
BROADWAY FESTIVAL.
ALL RIGHT, SO A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL GOES DOWN.
THROW SOME SCALLOPS IN.
SOMETHING YOU FIND
IN EVERY DINER AS YOU TRAVEL
AROUND THE COUNTRY--
NICE LOBSTER TAILS.
I'M GONNA THROW
THE SHRIMP.
I'M GONNA THROW THE MUSSELS,
OF COURSE, LIKE THAT.
YEAH, THIS IS
A SEAFOOD BUFFET FOR 90.
EVERYBODY'S STARTING
TO POP OPEN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH THE WINE.
LIKE A MAGIC SHOW.
YOU SEE THAT? YOU SEE HOW
HE STAYED RIGHT IN IT?
RUN THAT ON
SLO-MO FOR ME.
SEE WHAT I SAID?
ADD A LITTLE GARLIC,
FRESH TOMATO, BASIL...
I LOVE WHERE
THIS IS GOING.
SALT AND PEPPER.
THE MARINARA
YOU MADE, RIGHT?
YES.
MMM, CALAMARI IN LAST
SO IT DOESN'T GET TOUGH,
'CAUSE BY THE TIME
THAT GETS SERVED UP,
THAT CALAMARI WILL COOK
IN THAT SAUCE.
RIGHT.
THROW THE PASTA OVER HERE,
CHEESE--FETA CHEESE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
DISH IT OUT.
IF I LIVED
ON AN ISLAND
AND ALL WE HAD
TO EAT WAS SEAFOOD,
I DON'T THINK I WOULD GET
THAT MUCH SEAFOOD.
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK AT
THE JUICE. LOOK AT THE SAUCE.
THERE'S NO WAY YOU COULD
HAVE DONE THIS ANY BETTER.
THE PASTA'S AL DENTE.
I GO TO ITALIAN RESTAURANTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
AND I CAN'T FIND PASTA
THAT'S AL DENTE.
I HAVE NOTHING TO SAY,
MAN, OTHER THAN JUST, WOW.
DELICIOUS. THAT'S
PRETTY MUCH IT IN A WORD.
I COULDN'T EAT THAT WHOLE
THING. HOW FAR DID YOU GET?
YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
THAT'S THE TAP
RIGHT THERE?
GEORGE HAS HIS OWN WAY OF DOING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING...
LOOK AT THAT.
LIKE WRAPPING SALMON
IN POTATO...
SO THIS MIGHT BE
ONE OF THE COOLEST THINGS
I'VE EVER SEEN
ON TRIPLE D.
WITH SAUTéED SPINACH
AND A HOMEMADE SCAMPI SAUCE.
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
THE BUS TO FLAVOR TOWN
JUST STOPPED OFF
AT THE BROADWAY DINER.
THE POTATOES ARE CRUNCHY,
AND THE SPINACH--
IT'S SAUTéED GREAT.
IT ALL COMES TOGETHER
VERY NICELY.
RAPUNZEL, RAPUNZEL,
LET DOWN YOUR HAIR.
AND THAT PARTY'S
JUST STARTING.
GEORGE IS EVEN DOING
HIS OWN SPICES.
A GUY THAT TELLS ME THAT
HE'S TOASTING ALL THE SEEDS--
THAT'S REAL DEAL HOLYFIELD
RIGHT THERE.
NOW THIS IS GONNA
BE MADE FOR WHAT?
I USUALLY PUT EVERYTHING,
LIKE ON MY CREOLE.
THAT LOOKS
LIKE MARDI GRAS.
YOU'RE MAKING THE SEASONING
SPICE YOURSELF, FRESH VEGGIES.
I'D COME HERE
AT 4:00 IN THE MORNING...
MY PLEASURE.
AND AT 5:00
AND AT 6:00 AND AT 7:00.
WHICH ISN'T A PROBLEM.
HERE YOU GO.
THEY'RE OPEN
24 HOURS A DAY.
SO YOU CAN COME AT, LIKE,
3:00 OR 4:00 IN THE AFTERNOON
AND GET BREAKFAST,
AND STILL IT'S GOOD.
SO IS THE WHOLE
BIG DINNER EXPERIENCE.
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHAT I WANTED THIS MORNING.
FOR ME, COMING HERE
IS A SLICE OF AMERICA.
A SLICE GEORGE HAS BEEN DISHING
UP FOR ALMOST 40 YEARS,
SINCE HE CAME
TO THE U.S. FROM GREECE
AND STARTED IN THE FOOD BIZ
AS A DISHWASHER.
TWO EGGS, SCRAMBLED.
STILL COMMITTED
TO THE CLASSIC DINER
AS A PLACE ANYONE CAN COUNT ON.
HAVE HAVE EVERYTHING
YOU COULD THINK OF.
FOR A GOOD MEAL...
IT'S A MONSTER.
AT A GOOD PRICE.
AND THEY PILE
THE FOOD ON THE PLATE,
AND YOU GET
YOUR MONEY'S WORTH.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH OR DINNER,
THE QUANTITY
IS A BIT OVERWHELMING.
AND IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
YOU CAN GET
GREEK FOOD, MEXICAN FOOD,
AND THERE'S ALWAYS
SOMETHING DELICIOUS.
WHOO, WHOO! GOULASH!
YEP.
HUNGARIAN. BUTTER, A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL, BONELESS SHORT RIBS.
TAKE IT OFF THE BONE. LOOK AT
ALL THAT MARBLING OF THE--
IF YOU COOK
THIS LOW AND SLOW,
IT'LL BREAK APART AND THEN TONS
OF--TONS OF BIG FLAVOR IN THAT.
(whistles)
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG
WITH BUTTER, OLIVE OIL
AND BONELESS SHORT RIBS.
OKAY...
A LITTLE CELERY.
RED PEPPER--THAT'S RED.
I'M THROWING IN SOME GREEN,
THE SPANISH PAPRIKA.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE
OF THE PASTE, MY FLOUR.
SO YOU'RE GONNA
MAKE A LITTLE ROUX
WITH THE FAT
THAT'S ALREADY IN THERE?
A LITTLE WINE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S BIG BITE STYLE
RIGHT THERE, BABY. YEAH!
NOW WE GOT IT.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER
GOING DOWN,
A FORTIFIED TOMATO JUICE.
AND I NEED
A LOT OF CHICKEN STOCK.
EIGHT SHOULD DO IT.
GOOD, WE
COVER THE MEAT.
THAT BOUQUET GARNI STAYS
DOWN IN THERE, NICE HERBS.
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO PLUCK THAT OUT LATER,
AND WE'RE GONNA LET
THAT SIT THERE AND...
SIMMER FOR THREE HOURS.
SHOULD WE ADD
A LITTLE PASTA? GOULASH.
NO, YOU SAY GOULASH.
GOULASH.
YES.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BUTTER,
AND THIS IS
A LITTLE BIT OF CHEESE.
I'M GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE NEST LIKE THIS.
OKAY. A LITTLE SAUCE.
OH, YEAH.
AND MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S GOU-LICIOUS.
I LIKE THAT. "GOU-LICIOUS."
IT'S LIKE I'M FULL
ALREADY JUST LOOKING AT IT.
(Guy) DID YOU
GET ENOUGH?
YEAH. OH, I'M TAKING IT
HOME WITH ME.
COME HERE
WHEN YOU'RE HUNGRY.
JUST ALL OF IT
HAS JUST BEEN JUST DYNAMITE.
I CAN'T THANK YOU ENOUGH
FOR THE RECOMMENDATION, MAN.
OH.
YOU DID GOOD.
THANKS.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA DRIVE
THE BUS TO FLAVOR TOWN.
I'M GONNA DRIVE
THE BUS TO FLAVOR TOWN?
YES.
I WILL.
UP NEXT...
IS THIS THE REAL DEAL
IN COMFORT DINER FOOD?
ABSOLUTELY.
SALT LAKE CITY..
LOOK AT THAT. WINNER,
WINNER, BRISKET DINNER.
WHERE THIS PLACE IS SMOKIN'.
LOOK AT THOSE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
SO YOU E-MAILED ME
AND TOLD ME THERE'S
A JOINT IN SALT LAKE CITY
THAT'S GOT EVERYTHING
I'M LOOKING FOR ON TRIPLE D.
YOU GOT STAFF
RUNNING SOME HEAVY INK,
AND THIS IS
WHERE SCRATCH COOKING
MEANS THAT THEY'RE
SMOKING THEIR OWN SALMON
AND BRINING THEIR OWN
CORNED BEEF.
YOU MADE THE CALL.
I'M HERE--BLUE PLATE DINER.
CORNED BEEF HASH?
ALL RIGHT!
IT'S AWESOME.
YOU NEED
TO COME GET THIS.
SALMON AND EGGS.
HERE YOU GO,
YOUNG LADY.
FRESH, LOTS OF FLAVOR.
GOOD FOOD,
GREAT ENVIRONMENT.
THANK YOU.
THEY'RE QUICK.
IT'S ALWAYS HOPPIN'.
WE LOVE THIS PLACE.
CECILY AND JORDAN BLOXHAM
HAVE BEEN REGULARS FOR YEARS.
AND WHO WROTE TO ME?
WE BOTH DID.
ELAINE JONES...
HOW LONG
YOU BEEN COMING HERE?
OH, FOREVER.
SHE E-MAILED ME, TOO.
IS THIS THE REAL DEAL
IN COMFORT DINER FOOD?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S JUST LIKE, HEY, HANG OUT.
YOU SEAT YOURSELF--WHATEVER.
IT'S JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO HANG OUT AND GET FILLED UP.
ENJOY.
A JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING DINER...
I REALLY LIKE
THEIR OMELETS.
FROM A HOT TURKEY SANDWICH
TO SCRATCH-MADE
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
DELICIOUS.
THIS IS GOOD
COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S JUST A CLASSIC
AMERICAN DINER.
MOST EVERYTHING
IN THIS RESTAURANT'S
KIND OF A MEMORY I HAD
OF WHAT I LIKED BEST.
I'D GO TO MOM AND POP
RESTAURANTS...
THIS DUDE
ROAD-TRIPPED? NO.
OH, YEAH.
JOHN BOUZEK WAS ON THE ROAD
WHEN HE HIT SALT LAKE.
TOOK ABOUT A 2-MONTH ROAD TRIP
AROUND THE WEST, LOOKING FOR
A NEW TOWN AND SAW SALT LAKE
AND FELL IN LOVE WITH IT.
SO HE PUT DOWN
SOME ROOTS...
HOW'S EVERYTHING, YOU GUYS?
GREW SOME WICKED CHOPS...
JOHN'S GOT
SOME GOOD ONES.
YOU SEE THE YIN
AND THE YANG, HUH?
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER--
FULL FACIAL.
AND OPENED UP
THE BLUE PLATE.
HOW IS EVERYTHING,
YOU GUYS?
IT'S ONE OF THOSE PLACES
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE AT HOME.
CORNED BEEF HASH.
IF YOU'RE DOING
YOUR OWN CORNED BEEF.
GOT TRADITIONAL
PICKLING SPICE
WITH BAY LEAF,
MUSTARD SEED
AND NICE, BIG
FAT JUNIPER BERRY.
THAT'S ONE OF THE KISSES
RIGHT THERE IN PASTRAMI,
SO OF COURSE IT'S GONNA GO
WELL IN CORNED BEEF.
HIT UP THE OTHER SIDE.
GIVE IT THE SAME ATTENTION.
WE'LL COVER IT
WITH SOME FOIL.
WOW, WHAT A REACH.
THROW IT IN
THE WALK-IN OVERNIGHT.
WE'LL PULL IT
AFTER 24 HOURS,
THROW IT IN THE WATER, AND WE'RE
JUST GONNA LET IT DO ITS TIME.
FIVE HOURS.
I USUALLY CUT IT
SO IT DOESN'T...
SO YOU CAN GET IT OUT.
YOU GRAB BOTH PIECES OUT,
THROW 'EM ON THE TRAY, COOL 'EM.
WE THROW IT BACK IN THE WALK-IN
OVERNIGHT TO LET IT SET UP.
ALL THIS JUST
FOR CORNED BEEF HASH?
CORNED BEEF HASH--WE ALSO
USE IT IN OUR REUBEN.
IT'S THE BEST THAT THEY MAKE
IN THE WHOLE CITY.
LOOK AT THAT. DUDE, WINNER,
WINNER BRISKET DINNER.
THAT'S ENOUGH
FOR AN ORDER?
THAT IS ENOUGH
FOR AN ORDER.
WOW.
NOW IT'S NOT
A FULL ORDER.
I KNOW WHERE
THE ON BUTTON IS.
SOME GREEN PEPPERS
AND ONION,
AND THEN WE ADD
THE CORNED BEEF.
WE HAVE POTATOES,
GREEN ONION.
SEE THAT LITTLE CRISP
RIGHT THERE?
THAT'S WHEN IT'S MONEY.
OH, YOU DON'T WANT TO GO BACK
WITH YOUR FRIENDS? OKAY.
THEN YOU THROW
THE CHEESE.
AAH!
LET THAT MELT THROUGH.
THAT IS
A MESS OF HASH.
CORNED BEEF IS GREAT.
NOT FALLING APART BUT TENDER.
THAT'S SOME
MONEY HASH. MMM.
NICE, MAN. I'M REALLY IMPRESSED
YOU'RE MAKING THE HASH.
OH, IT'S WAY GOOD.
IT'S SO CHEESY.
NICE AND SAVORY.
IT'S GOOD.
EVERYTHING I'VE
HAD HERE I JUST LOVE.
DIDN'T TAKE VERY LONG
FOR IT TO GET POPULAR.
FROM THE DAY WE OPENED, WE
WERE BUSY AND PEOPLE LOVED IT.
SOMETIMES WE HAVE TO GET UP
VERY EARLY TO GET IN HERE
BECAUSE IT'S SO PACKED.
FOOD'S GREAT. THERE'S PLENTY
OF GOOD STUFF TO EAT HERE.
WHATEVER YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
THEY'RE EVEN SCRATCH-MAKING
VEGGIE BURGERS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THAT'S A MONSTER PATTY.
I WOULD ORDER THAT
AGAIN IN A HEARTBEAT.
GOT A KID'S CAKE.
THAT YOU OVER HERE?
YEAH, WE'VE GOT
A FAVORITE.
IT'S THE COUNTRY CORNCAKES
THAT THEY SPECIALIZE IN.
OUT OF THE ITEMS
THAT YOU HAVE ON YOUR MENU,
HOW MANY ARE HANDMADE?
AT LEAST 75%.
I MEAN, WE TRY TO MAKE AS MUCH
AS WE CAN FROM HOMEMADE.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE SALMON
HE'S SMOKING OUT BACK.
WHY WE COME HERE
IS FOR THE SALMON.
WE HAVE A SALMON RUB--
SALT, SUGAR, CAYENNE PEPPER,
ALLSPICE AND OLD BAY.
PUT A PRETTY
LIBERAL AMOUNT.
YOU LOOK LIKE
THE PIZZA DELIVERY GUY.
I FEEL LIKE
THROW SOME OF THE HICKORY
CHIPS ON THERE,
KIND OF OFFSET IT AND LET IT
COOK FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
GIVE IT A LITTLE DIRECT HEAT
AND THEN PULL IT BACK OFF.
SO OVERALL, YOU'RE TAKING
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF?
ABOUT TWO WHEN
IT'S ALL SAID AND DONE.
ABOUT TWO HOURS
SAID AND DONE. (whistles)
YEAH, SO THERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THOSE.
NICE LITTLE GLAZE ON TOP,
AND WHAT DOES THIS GO ON?
SALMON, ONION,
TOMATO BENEDICT...
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S WONDERFUL.
(John) AND WE HAVE
A SALMON CLUB IT GOES ON.
I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER HAD
A FRESHLY SMOKED
SALMON CLUB SANDWICH.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
IT MIGHT BE A FIRST.
WE HAVE
SOME BASIL MAYO.
WE THROW DOWN
SOME LETTUCE, TOMATO,
A LITTLE HAVARTI CHEESE...
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
COUPLE SLICES OF BACON,
PUT THAT ON THERE.
(whistles)
GIVE THAT A BITE.
MMM.
I GOTTA TELL YOU, DUDE,
SMOKED SALMON CLUB WORKS.
WOW. YOU DON'T SKIMP WHEN
IT COMES TO DOING IT RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT PEPPER BACON RIGHT
THERE WITH THE BASIL MAYO.
THAT IS AWESOME.
REALLY GOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD FOOD.
I'VE NEVER BEEN DISAPPOINTED.
IT'S GOT
A GREAT VARIETY.
(Guy) DID I JUST SEE A TAMALE
GO OUT OF HERE A MINUTE AGO?
WE DID.
AND IT'S NOT JUST TAMALES.
JOHN'S DOING ALL KINDS
OF MEXICAN FOOD.
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
BURRITO.
AND MORE...
LOOKS GREAT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
QUITE THE STAND-UP
PLATE RIGHT THERE.
SALMON CLUB,
CORNED BEEF HASH AND EGG.
THANK YOU.
AT THE BLUE PLATE DINER
IN SALT LAKE CITY...
CAJUN FRIES FOR YOU.
FORMER ROAD-TRIPPER
JOHN BOUZEK...
MORE COFFEE OVER HERE?
SETTLED DOWN
TO DO CLASSIC DINER.
GOOD FOOD, GOOD PORTION,
GOOD VALUE.
IT'S JUST
A COOL LITTLE DINER.
FROM HOMEMADE HASH...
IT'S BETTER THAN ANY
I'VE EVER HAD BEFORE.
TO FRESH SALMON
SMOKED RIGHT OUT BACK.
IT'S AWESOME.
AND GET THIS...
BURRITO?
HOMEMADE MEXICAN
AND A SOUTHWESTERN SPECIALTY.
PORK CHILI VERDE.
PERFECT COMBINATION
OF EVERYTHING.
WE USE LARD.
THE OTHER WHITE FAT.
EXACTLY.
SOME PORK, PORK BUTT.
SO THAT'S GONNA COOK DOWN...
AND WE'LL STEP BACK OVER HERE
WHERE WE CAN BE WORKING
ON THE PUREE
OF SERRANO PEPPERS...
WELL, AT LEAST
THAT'S NOT GONNA BE HOT.
DICED TOMATOES AND JUICE.
WE'LL THROW IN SOME SALT,
WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES...
AS YOU SHOULD.
AND DICED ONIONS AND WE'LL JUST
LET THAT FLY FOR A LITTLE BIT.
DICED GREEN CHILIES
INTO THE POT THAT'S BOILING.
AND THEN THE MIXTURE
OF THE SERRANOS.
SO THAT'S STARTING
TO COOK UP NICE.
WE'LL STIR THIS AND THEN
WE'LL PUT SOME ROUX IN THERE.
WE USE HALF FLOUR,
HALF LARD.
HALF FLOUR, HALF LARD.
YEAH.
SO LARD IS YOUR--YOU'RE
USING SOME KIND OF A FAT.
NOW WE PUT THE PORK IN.
HOW LONG DOES THAT TAKE?
IT'D BE ABOUT
AN HOUR AND A HALF.
NOW WHERE'D THIS
RECIPE COME FROM?
THIS IS ACTUALLY LEE,
WHO'S MY HEAD KITCHEN GUY--
IT'S HIS GRANDMOTHER'S
PORK CHILI VERDE, AND IT'S GOOD.
WOW, WAY TO TAKE
THE FAMILY RECIPE.
YEAH.
WE START BY
HEATING UP A TORTILLA.
GRAB SOME
PORK CHILI VERDE.
HO HO.
WE'RE GONNA
THROW SOME RICE,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
BLACK BEANS TO THAT.
AND WHAT'S
IN THE BLACK BEANS?
SALSA, GARLIC,
DICED TOMATOES,
GREEN CHILIES, CHEESE,
AND WE THROW MORE
CHILI VERDE ON IT.
I MEAN, AM I SUPPOSED TO TAP
AT SOME POINT AND SAY ENOUGH?
NOT HERE. EVERYTHING'S BIG
HERE AT THE DINER.
THAT'S GONNA BE HOT.
THERE YOU GO. LOOK AT THAT.
WARRIOR.
MMM. MONEY, DUDE. SO MONEY.
IT'S GOT GREAT PORK FLAVOR.
IT'S GOT GOOD SPICE TO IT,
AND I MEAN, I LIKE SPICE,
BUT THAT'S
GOT SOME HEAT.
THE BEANS ARE NICE AND TENDER.
RICE ISN'T OVERCOOKED.
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK AT
THE CHEESE LEVEL, MAN.
I MEAN, THERE'S LIKE
A 1/2-POUND OF CHEESE ON THERE.
GRANDMA DID ALL RIGHT?
GRANDMA JOHN
DID ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
PRETTY SPICY.
VERY TASTY.
EVERY SINGLE THING
ON THE MENU IS JUST UNBEATABLE.
THANKS, GUYS.
THE ATMOSPHERE IS FABULOUS.
APPRECIATE YOU GUYS
COMING IN TODAY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
DELICIOUS.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY,
CORNED BEEF HASH AND EGGS.
(Guy) WHAT'S THE 1-WORD
STATEMENT ABOUT THIS PLACE?
YOU ALWAYS GET
A CRAVING FOR IT.
CRAVING...
YEAH, THAT'S
MORE THAN ONE.
I CAN'T DESCRIBE IT
IN ONE WORD.
I WANT TO BE YOU
FOR A MINUTE, OKAY?
OH, GOSH.
HERE WE GO.
NOW YOU GOTTA BE ABLE TO MAKE
THE FACE AND EVERYTHING.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
DID YOU GET
THE THUMBS UP?
IF SHE BLEACHES
HER HAIR, I'M DONE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY
MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE D.
TELL ME ABOUT THE OMELET-INFUSED
VODKA YOU'VE BEEN DOING.
I WANT TO HAVE SOME
OF THAT LIVER-INFUSED GIN.
I THINK I FEEL LIKE A FRIED
CHICKEN MOJITO COMING ON.
I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN DO.