HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
WHOO! THAT'S AWFULLY GOOD.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU THINK IT WOULD BE
CHILI DOGS OR FRIES.
TOTALLY UNEXPECTED.
BISON HASH.
I WOULDN'T DRIVE BY HERE
AND ANTICIPATE THAT.
KIND OF A SECRET GEM.
IT'S SAN ANTONIO...
THE FOOD IS ORGANIC,
AND IT'S FRESH.
SERIOUS COOKING...
THE MOROCCAN
SWEET POTATO SALAD.
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
AT A CAR WASH
AND LAUNDROMAT.
IN THE MIDDLE
OF A FULL-BLOWN RESTAURANT.
IT'S A LITTLE FUNKY.
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
GOT AN ECLECTIC CUISINE.
MMM.
WHERE DINNER
AT THE BOWLING ALLEY...
YOU GOT BOWLING. YOU GOT
GOOD FOOD. IT'S GREAT.
MEANS FREE-RANGE BISON...
MMM.
AND SMOKED TROUT SALAD.
JUST WHAT I EXPECT
WHEN I WALK THROUGH
AND I WANT TO GET
A SIZE 10 1/2 BOWLING SHOE.
AND IN ATLANTA...
WOW. THAT'S GOT
ALL KINDS OF FLAVOR.
A GROCERY STORE...
IT'S A FUN EXPERIENCE.
MOZZARELLA.
WHERE THEY'LL COOK IT
FOR YOU...
LOVE THE SMELL. LOOK AT THAT
MIXTURE. MORE SOUP, PLEASE.
AND WAIT TILL YOU SEE
WHAT YOU GET.
QUAIL ON A WAFFLE?
THAT'S GREAT, BUT WEIRD...
(laughs)
BUT IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M TRAVELING
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
SO IT'S NICE ONCE IN A WHILE
TO BE ABLE TO STOP
AND WASH DOWN THE '67.
SO HERE I AM
IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
AND THE ONLY FOOD
I'VE EVER GOT AT A CAR WASH
HAS COME OUT
OF A VENDING MACHINE,
SO YOU GOT TO KNOW
I WAS TOTALLY BLOWN AWAY
TO FIND OUT CONNECTED
TO THIS CAR WASH
IS A TOTALLY LEGIT RESTAURANT
CALLED THE COVE.
(woman) I'LL TAKE
A LAMB BURGER.
CAN I GET THE FISH TACO?
(woman) ORDER UP.
THE FOOD IS ORGANIC
AND IT'S FRESH.
SPINACH SALAD
AND SEAFOOD SAMPLER.
YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT SOMETHING
LIKE THIS AT A PLACE LIKE THIS.
IT'S A CAR WASH...
OH, YEAH, AND A LAUNDROMAT.
IN THE MIDDLE
IS A FULL-BLOWN RESTAURANT.
IT'S A LITTLE FUNKY.
WHOO! THAT'S AWFULLY GOOD.
LISA ASVESTAS...
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA HAVE?
AND HER HUSBAND SAM...
THERE YOU GO.
STARTED OUT
SERVING SANDWICHES.
I ALWAYS WANTED TO DO MORE.
I WAS LIKE,
"CAN I HAVE A GRILL?"
AND THEN SAM
WOULD PUT IN A GRILL.
"CAN I HAVE A GRIDDLE?"
THEN THEY STARTED
HAVING COOKS...
PAPER DOWN.
AND ENDED UP WITH...
A C.I.A.-TRAINED CHEF.
THAT'S MICHAEL SOHOCKI,
WHO IS LOOKING TO BUILD A MENU
HE CAN HAVE SOME FUN WITH...
WOW, LOOK AT THE SMOKE
COMING OUT OF THAT!
AND THEN BEFORE WE KNEW IT,
WE HAD A FULL RESTAURANT.
HEAVY ON FRESH,
ORGANIC AND HOMEMADE.
FROM SCRATCH-MADE MOROCCAN
SWEET POTATO SALAD...
WOW, THAT'S DYNAMITE.
QUESADILLA UP.
TO VEGGIE QUESADILLAS
WITH PORTOBELLO MUSHROOMS
AND ORGANIC SPINACH...
IT'S GOT A NICE KICK.
AND THIS CROWD FAVORITE...
LAMB BURGER.
THE LAMB BURGER,
MAN, IS AWESOME.
JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF SPICE.
CUMIN, CORIANDER,
WHOLE BLACK PEPPER.
RIGHT.
ALWAYS START
WITH THE WHOLE SEED,
'CAUSE I WANT THE SMOKY
TASTE INSIDE THE MEAT.
THAT'S SWEET.
FILLS THE WHOLE KITCHEN
WITH THE SMELL
OF THE ROASTING SPICES.
SEASON WIZARD.
I PUT THIS
INSIDE THE LAMB.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I EXPECTED
WHEN I DROVE UP
TO WASH THE '67.
CHOPPED FRESH GARLIC...
JUST A TOUCH OF CAYENNE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
THIS IS KOSHER SALT.
OKAY, SO WE GOT THAT
ALL MIXED UP.
YEP.
TAKE A PATTY.
ABOUT 5 1/2 OUNCE.
SO WHILE THAT'S GRILLING,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SAUCE?
RIGHT.
ANCHO, PASILLA AND...
PULLA--THE PULLA PEPPER.
IT'S GONNA "PULL YA" OVER
TO THE BEER COUNTER
TO GET ANOTHER ONE.
LIME JUICE,
OLIVE OIL.
THERE YOU GO.
I HAVE A WHOLE
CLOVE OF GARLIC
AND A TABLESPOON
OF KOSHER SALT.
SOME SOUR CREAM.
AND THEN I FINISH IT
WITH JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAVY CREAM.
TO KIND OF GIVE IT
A NICE SILKINESS--SMOOTH.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S NOT...
THAT'S NOT AS HOT
AS I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA BE.
(no audio)
NICE GRILL MARKS ON THAT.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE, TOO.
I WISH YOU WOULD HAVE
MADE YOURSELF ONE.
IS THIS THE CIABATTA ROLL?
WE'RE GONNA THROW THIS ON
THE GRILL AND WARM IT UP?
YES, ABSOLUTELY.
YOU READY?
IT'S STILL NICE
AND JUICY INSIDE.
OH, YEAH.
(whistles)
BETTER LOVE THAT SAUCE.
OKAY.
IT'S GOT SO MUCH FLAVOR.
THE CHEESE IS COTIJA.
COTIJA.
MEXICO'S ANSWER TO FETA.
RIGHT.
WE USE IT
LIKE A SEASONING.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
AND THEN I PUT
SLICED RED ONION
AND LOTS OF TOMATOES.
JUICY, JUICY, JUICY.
BABY GREENS.
WANT HALF?
PLEASE.
IT'S YOUR KITCHEN.
TAKE A LOOKEY-LOO AT THAT.
(whistles)
WOW. THAT'S LIKE A MILK SHAKE
IN A BUN, MAN.
OH. MMM. MMM!
THAT'S NOT GONNA CUT IT.
I NEED, LIKE, A BLANKET.
SOME OF THE BEST LAMB BURGER
I'VE EVER HAD.
AT A CAR WASH?
NUTS.
IT'S JUST THE BASICS,
BUT WE'RE GONNA USE
THE GOOD OILS, THE GOOD HERBS,
THE GOOD SPICES.
OUR PRODUCE IS ORGANIC
WHEN WE CAN GET IT
AND LOCALLY GROWN
WHEN WE CAN GET IT.
OUR MEATS ARE GRASS-FED MEATS.
WHAT WAS THE FIRST
OUT-OF-THE-BOX ITEM?
THE FISH TACO.
LISA'S ORIGINAL RECIPE.
I GOT HOOKED
ON THE FISH TACOS,
AND I GOT HOOKED
ON SAM AND LISA.
(Lisa) HOMEMADE COLESLAW,
OUR POBLANO SAUCE
ACROSS THE TOP.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK I SHOULDN'T HAVE
GIVEN YOU THE OTHER HALF.
IT'S EXTREMELY FRESH.
EXCELLENT.
PORTOBELLO
SPINACH QUESADILLA.
VERY GOOD.
VERY DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A MARINADE
FOR OUR PORTOBELLOS.
BALSAMIC VINEGAR
WITH EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
I WANT
TO EMULSIFY THIS FIRST.
YOU GONNA
EMULSIFY IT TOGETHER?
RIGHT.
FRESH GROUND PEPPERCORN.
FRESH GARLIC--
GOT TO HAVE THAT.
OKAY.
SALT, HERBES de PROVENCE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THAT MIGHT BE ONE OF
THE FIRST TIMES I'VE EVER SEEN
HERBES de PROVENCE
BROUGHT INTO PLAY.
SAVORY THYME, ROSEMARY, BASIL,
TARRAGON AND LAVENDER FLOWERS.
EH, LAVENDER FLOWERS.
I MEAN, THAT'S--
LOOK AT THAT.
AND WE'RE GONNA POUR
THAT ALL IN THERE.
THAT'S A SAVORY SYRUP.
TASTE IT.
MMM, MMM, MMM.
WE USE OUR HANDS.
WE WANT TO COAT 'EM
REALLY GOOD.
THROW THEM ON THE GRILL
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
OKAY, WELL, WE CAN MAKE
THE POBLANO SAUCE.
POBLANOS AND SERRANOS?
SERRANOS.
GET THE MAJORITY OF THE SKIN
OFF, GET THE SEEDS OUT.
DON'T WASH IT DOWN
IN THE WATER.
GONNA ADD OUR YOGURT.
GOOD FOR YOU.
MAYONNAISE AND SOUR CREAM.
SOUR CREAM?
SOME SALT.
FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
DID YOU GRIND
THAT PEPPER, TOO?
YES, WE DID.
WE GRIND ALL OUR PEPPER.
OH!
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
A NICE BIG--WAH--
THERE'S A LOT OF HEAT.
GONNA FIDDLE
WITH THE GRIDDLE?
WITH THE GRIDDLE.
OKAY, WHOLE GRAIN TORTILLA
MADE LOCALLY.
TAKE OUR PORTOBELLO
MUSHROOM--SLICE IT UP.
ON THE FLATTOP
OR ON THE TORTILLA?
ON THE FLATTOP.
THERE YOU GO. NOW WE WANT
TO ADD OUR RED ONIONS.
YEP.
THAT'S PLENTY,
PLENTY, PLENTY.
ORGANIC SPINACH--
ALL OF THE SPINACH.
ALL OF IT?
YEAH, IT'S GONNA
SHRINK A LOT.
FLOP THE TORTILLA--
NICE AND TOASTY.
THERE WE GO.
I'M GONNA COVER THIS
FOR JUST A SECOND.
TO WILT THAT SPINACH
A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, WILT THE SPINACH.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
CAN WE GET A LITTLE
WATER IN THAT?
OKAY, THIS IS READY.
CHEESE.
CHEESE!
DO THE CHEESE. OKAY.
WHAT KIND OF CHEESE
WE GOT?
JACK.
MY MOM AND MY SISTER
ARE GOING NUTS RIGHT NOW
WATCHING THIS.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
FOLD IT OVER.
SOME SAUCE--
CONTAINER OF SAUCE.
THE POBLANO-SERRANO SAUCE.
THERE YOU GO.
THEY'RE READY.
HUH. MMM!
THAT'S GOOD.
I ALREADY FEEL HEALTHIER.
YOU LOOK HEALTHY.
KEEP THE CAR.
I'M GONNA WALK THE STATES.
THAT SAUCE
FITS IT PERFECTLY.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
I WOULD THE CLEANEST
CAR IN SAN ANTONIO
IF I KNEW THIS WAS HERE.
IT'S GOT SOME SPICE
TO IT.
IT TAKES A TEX-MEX BASIC
AND MAKES IT
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
DIFFERENT? YOU THINK?
IT'S ONE OF THE PLACES
YOU WANT TO BRING YOUR FRIENDS
BECAUSE IT'S JUST SO WEIRD
AND SO CRAZY.
MOROCCAN POTATO SALAD?
KIND OF A SECRET GEM PLACE
THAT WE HAVE IN OUR CITY.
SHRIMP TACO?
IT'S JUST ALL
COME TOGETHER.
WHEN YOU HAVE A PASSION
FOR SOMETHING
AND YOU WORK HARD AT IT,
IT KIND OF WORKS OUT.
THE ONLY THING THAT
I DON'T LIKE ABOUT THIS
IS THAT...
IT'S ALL GONE.
I'LL MAKE YOU
ANOTHER ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M HAPPY.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE ROLLING TO MINNEAPOLIS.
BETWEEN FRAMES,
YOU CAN EAT A LITTLE DINNER.
LIKE AHI TUNA...
I DIDN'T EXPECT
TO FIND THAT.
AND BISON HASH.
NICE AND SIZZLE-Y.
DID YOU JUST SAY
"NICE AND SIZZLE-Y"?
YEAH, I SURE DID.
WHEN I WAS A KID
AND MY PARENTS TOLD ME
WE WERE GONNA HAVE DINNER
AT THE BOWLING ALLEY,
I WAS TOTALLY STOKED,
BUT AS I GOT OLDER,
I DON'T THINK I WAS TOO DOWN
WITH BOWLING ALLEY FOOD,
UNLESS I FIND MYSELF
IN MINNEAPOLIS
HAVING DINNER
AT BRYANT-LAKE BOWL.
I WOULD NEVER EXPECT
TO FIND THIS AT A BOWLING ALLEY.
BISON HASH.
THEY EVEN LET YOU EAT
NEAR THEIR BOWLING LANES.
THIS PLACE IS MONEY. MMM.
BUT I DIDN'T EXPECT
TO FIND THAT.
(woman) THE AHI TUNA.
IT'S AMAZING.
YOU THINK IT WOULD BE
CHILI DOGS OR FRIES.
(man) HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
IT'S KIND OF
ECLECTIC CUISINE.
CRANKED OUT BY HEAD CHEF
AL POTYONDY-SMITH.
WE REALLY FOCUS ON
LOCAL, SUSTAINABLE, ORGANIC.
FRENCH TOAST IS ABOUT TO GO.
THERE'S HOMEMADE GRANOLA
FOR THE PANCAKES,
SMOKED LOCAL TROUT,
AND CHECK OUT THIS FAVORITE.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE
ABOUT THE HASH?
IT'S MADE WITH BISON.
INITIALLY IT STARTED
WITH CORNED BEEF HASH,
BUT THEN WE DECIDED IT WOULD BE
REALLY WAY COOLER
TO HAVE OURSELVES SOME ORGANIC
GRASS-FED FREE-RANGE BISON.
YOU DON'T GET
THAT EVERY DAY.
FIRST STEP,
YOU GOT TO FRY YOUR POTATO,
AND A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER ON THOSE.
OKAY, SO HOW
ARE THOSE LOOKING?
THESE ARE LOOKING
ABOUT DONE.
RIGHT ON THE TOP THERE,
FRESH PARLEY, CHIVES AND THYME.
OKAY, SO THE POTATOES
ARE DONE. NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
LET'S START OUR SAUTé.
A LITTLE PURIFIED BUTTER,
'CAUSE IT DOESN'T BURN
AS QUICKLY.
THAT'S A LOT OF BUTTER
TO CLARIFY.
A LITTLE FRESH GARLIC,
RED ONION,
GREEN AND RED PEPPERS.
AND OF COURSE, A LITTLE BIT
MORE SALT AND PEPPER.
GET THAT SAUTéING.
NOW WE CAN ADD OUR BISON.
OKAY.
THIS IS A TOP ROUND PRODUCT
SHAVED REALLY THIN.
THE BISON IS COOKED
TO ORDER FOR EACH HASH?
THAT'S CORRECT.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
AND I LIKE TO HAVE THIS
BE A LITTLE MEDIUM,
ESPECIALLY 'CAUSE I'M GONNA
THROW IT IN THE PAN AGAIN.
THAT'S BISON'S ABOUT READY
TO COME OFF AND GET CHOPPED UP.
WE'LL THROW OUR BISON IN,
MIX IT UP REAL GOOD.
JUST TAKE A NICE CHUNK
FULL OF POTATOES.
WE LIKE TO CHOP 'EM
UP A LITTLE BIT,
SO THAT IT'S A LITTLE BIT
MORE LIKE A HASH.
GOT IT.
GET THOSE IN THE PAN.
LOOKS GREAT.
THANK YOU. I THINK
IT'S PRETTY READY TO ROLL.
MMM. I GOT
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
(laughs)
GOOD STUFF.
YEAH, I'M PROUD
OF THAT ONE.
IT'S REAL FLAVORFUL BISON.
POTATOES HAVE A LITTLE CRUNCH.
NICE FRESHNESS
OUT OF THE PEPPERS.
I COULD JUST PUT
A POUNDING ON THIS.
COOL.
THIS HASH IS AWESOME.
IT'S NOT HEAVY.
IT'S NOT GREASY.
I'M TELL YOU,
THE FOOD'S REALLY GOOD,
AND IT'S REALLY FRESH.
I LOVE IT.
I COME HERE EVERY WEEK.
I HAVE SOME FOOD
FOR YOU GUYS.
EXACTLY WHAT KIM BARTMANN
HAD IN MIND...
QUESADILLA, LADIES?
WHEN SHE WALKED INTO
THIS JOINT 15 YEARS AGO...
THAT'S YOURS.
FOUND THE OWNER AND SAID...
"I WANT TO BUY
YOUR BOWLING ALLEY,"
AND HE WAS LIKE,
"YOU'RE NUTS."
MAYBE, BUT IT WORKED.
THE SHOE COUNTER
USED TO BE HERE.
AND THE LANES ARE RIGHT WHERE
THEY ALWAYS WERE...
THEY PRESERVED THE BEST.
EVEN ROGER.
ROGER!
HE CAME
WITH THE PLACE, TOO.
AND YOU KNOW HOW
TO FIX ALL OF THIS?
PRETTY MUCH.
THEY'RE LUCKY
TO HAVE YOU, BUDDY.
YOU GOT BOWLING. YOU GOT
GOOD FOOD. IT'S GREAT.
WHATEVER AL'S CRANKING OUT.
ORGANIC TROUT
AND BEET SALADS.
IT'S GREAT WHEN YOU WANT
TO HAVE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
SMOKED TROUT
AND BEET SALAD?
I LIKE THE SOUNDS OF ALL
OF THAT. I'M A BIG BEET FAN.
GONNA ROAST THEM?
YEP. A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL.
IN THE OVEN.
AT ABOUT 350
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT THOSE BAD BOYS.
NICE. CHECK THE DONENESS.
SO YOU TAKE
THE SKINS OFF AND THEN...
JULIENNE THEM.
LET'S GO MAKE THE SALAD.
THIS IS GREEN
GODDESS DRESSING.
FIRST, WE WANT TO ADD
A LITTLE MINCED GARLIC,
FRESH CHOPPED TARRAGON,
FRESH CHIVES,
CHOPPED ITALIAN PARSLEY,
MILK, PLAIN YOGURT,
CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR.
THAT ENOUGH ACID?
AND THEN THIS IS SOME
FRESH-SQUEEZED LIME JUICE.
OKAY.
SOME GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED MAYONNAISE.
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
START WITH THE BEETS,
SHREDDED TROUT,
SOME CUCUMBERS THAT
WE WANT TO PUT IN THERE.
OOH, YEAH. LET'S GIVE YOU
A LITTLE MORE ACCESS.
MMM. YOU KNOW, THAT BEET
GOES PERFECT WITH IT. MONEY.
JUST WHAT I EXPECT
WHEN I WALK THROUGH
AND I WANT TO GET
A SIZE 10 1/2 BOWLING SHOE,
AND I'M GONNA HAVE
A SALAD LIKE THAT.
EXCELLENT.
MAKES A LOT OF SENSE.
EVEN A BASIC LIKE WINGS
GET DONE UP RIGHT...
BETTER THAN
THE REGULAR OLD HOT?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S GOT A NICE SPICE.
WITH A HOMEMADE
BLUE CHEESE DRESSING.
IT'S NICE AND REFRESHING.
A LITTLE CONFUSING TO BE HAVING
A NICE MEAL AND THEN HEARING...
(imitates pins crashing)
IT IS, BUT, HEY,
IT'S COOL.
I DON'T CARE ABOUT THE NOISE.
I CARE ABOUT THIS GETTING FULL.
HOW'S THE PHAD THAI?
VERY GOOD.
THAT'S RIGHT--
THAI COOKING, TOO.
YOU EVER GO TO THE OPERA
AND HAVE NACHOS?
GOOD COMBINATION, THOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE PHAD THAI.
VEGETARIAN VERSION--THROW
IN YOUR BROWN SUGAR HERE.
TAMARIND PASTE,
AND THAT'S A HOT CHILI PASTE.
A LITTLE RICE VINEGAR.
SEASONED OR UNSEASONED?
UNSEASONED.
AND HERE WE HAVE A LITTLE
SWEET RICE WINE VINEGAR,
AND FINALLY,
WE HAVE HERE TAMARI.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
EARTHY FLAVOR OF SOY.
OKAY, YOU WHISK
THAT TOGETHER.
YEP. WHOMP, WHOMP, WHOMP.
AND HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA LET THAT REDUCE?
USUALLY ABOUT 15,
MAYBE 18 MINUTES.
DIG IT. SO HOT PAN.
WHAT ARE THE VEGGIES THAT
WE'RE GONNA ADD IN THERE?
FRESH MINCED GARLIC,
JULIENNE RED ONION,
JULIENNE CARROTS, AS WELL.
WE LIKE THAT CRUNCH IN THERE.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPER, SALT.
LET THAT FRY UP
FOR A SECOND.
NICE AND SIZZLE-Y.
DID YOU JUST SAY
"NICE AND SIZZLE-Y"?
YEAH, I SURE DID.
YOU WANT TO ADD
SOME RICE-STICK NOODLES.
BLANCH THOSE TO AL DENTE?
YEP.
GIVE THEM KIND OF
A LITTLE CRUNCHY FRY THERE.
ONCE THAT'S HAPPENED,
A LITTLE OF THAT
LOVELY PHAD THAI
SAUCE WE JUST MADE.
LET THAT SIMMER
FOR A SECOND.
NOODLES ARE CONTINUING
TO COOK
AND ABSORB A LITTLE BIT.
EXACTLY.
CAN IT GET SERVED
WITH CHICKEN IF PEOPLE WANT?
ABSOLUTELY.
CHICKEN,
PORK IF THEY WANT IT.
GOOD TO GO.
OKAY, WITH ALL
THE COLD GARNISH ON TOP.
THAT'S RIGHT--
CHOPPED PEANUTS.
MUNG BEAN SPROUTS.
CILANTRO AND A LITTLE
FRESH LIME.
DYNAMITE. GREAT FLAVOR.
THIS IS BETTER THAN SOME THAT
I'VE HAD IN THAI RESTAURANTS.
THE ONLY QUESTION
IS CAN I GET SOME CHOPSTICKS?
OH, YEAH.
WE HAVE THOSE HERE.
YOU HAVE THE CHOPSTICKS
AT A BOWLING ALLEY?
AND WE GOT CHOPSTICKS.
I'D ORDER IT MANY TIMES.
FANTASTIC.
VERY GOOD. MY FIRST TIME
HAVING PHAD THAI.
(woman) IT'S GOT
A LOT OF FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S REALLY CRISPY.
YOU HAVE OFFICIAL CHOPSTICKS
AND EVERYTHING.
I'M FANCY, THOUGH.
I ROLL LIKE THAT.
THAT'S ACTUALLY A PRETTY GOOD
ONE TO USE AT A BOWLING ALLEY.
THAT'S HOW I ROLL.
I THINK
IT'S A NICE COMBINATION HERE.
BETWEEN GAMES,
YOU CAN EAT A LITTLE DINNER.
THEY JUST KNOW HOW
TO DO IT RIGHT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
AND IT'S FRESH. I LOVE IT.
GOOD TIMES.
HAVE A LITTLE DINNER,
AND GO THROW SOME PINS.
IT'S NOT LIKE
GOING OUT ALMOST, YOU KNOW?
IT'S WHERE YOU GO
WHEN YOU'RE HUNGRY.
IT'S DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND BOWLING ALLEYS.
UP NEXT...
I'M GONNA BRING
YOU GUYS SOME QUAIL.
WE'RE HEADING FOR
A NEIGHBORHOOD GROCERY STORE
IN ATLANTA...
FOR A FOODIE WHO WANTS
TO STAY IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
THIS IS LIKE A DREAM.
IF YOU'RE DREAMING
OF FROGMORE STEW.
SPICY?
YEAH! THAT'S GREAT.
SO HERE I AM ROLLING THROUGH
AN OLD HISTORIC NEIGHBORHOOD
IN ATLANTA, GEORGIA,
CALLED CABBAGETOWN,
WHERE THEY'VE KEPT UP
THE BUILDINGS
AND WHERE THIS JOINT'S BEEN
HERE SINCE THE '20s.
OUTSIDE, IT LOOKS LIKE
A NEIGHBORHOOD GROCERY STORE.
INSIDE, IT'S SOMETHING
TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
ALL RIGHTY.
HAD THE QUAIL
AND A WAFFLE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
TRYING THE FROGMORE STEW.
I HAD THE MOZZARELLA, TOMATO
AND BASIL ON A BAGUETTE--
FANTASTIC.
I THOUGHT THE MEATBALL
SLIDERS WERE GREAT.
AND I ALWAYS
WANT TO SEARCH
FOR THE PERFECT
FRIED DILL PICKLE.
THEY'RE SO YUMMY.
WHEN YOU'RE IN THE MOOD FOR
SOMETHING DIFFERENT, WHY NOT?
THEY'VE HAD
A BASIC LUNCH COUNTER
HERE AT THE CABBAGETOWN MARKET
FOR DECADES...
THE BURGER.
ALL SORTS OF SANDWICHES.
BUT TWO AND A HALF YEARS AGO,
LISA HANSON...
OKAY.
AND MARIA LOCKE
BOUGHT THE JOINT...
MOZZARELLA?
AND STARTED ADDING THE KINDS
OF DISHES THEY LOVED TO MAKE.
I'M GONNA BRING
YOU GUYS SOME QUAIL.
EVERYBODY HAS THIS,
OF COURSE, RIGHT THERE
ON THEIR SANDWICH TABLE--
WALNUT OIL.
WHAT IS THIS
LAB EXPERIMENT?
WHAT IS THAT?
A 6-HEADED FROG?
THAT'S THE HABANERO
VINEGAR,
AND IT WILL CURE
ANY DISEASE.
YEE-HAW!
OH, IT'S JUST
AN ECLECTIC MIX.
JUST WHATEVER YOU'RE
IN THE MOOD FOR.
LET ME GET SOME
OF THIS STEW, BABY.
YOU GOT TO TRY
THE FROGMORE STEW.
NAMED AFTER AN ISLAND
OFF THE COAST OF--
IT'S RIGHT ON THE BORDER
OF SOUTH CAROLINA AND GEORGIA.
WITH FROG?
NO FROGS AND NO STEW.
NO FROG...
NO FROG.
AND NO STEW--
JUST A NAME.
YEAH, I'VE GOT SHRIMP,
ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
PRETTY MUCH
LIKE A LOW-COUNTRY BOIL.
SO YOU BOIL SOME WATER.
AND THEN THROW IN
SOME BEER.
EQUAL AMOUNTS BEER TO WATER.
SOME PEOPLE USE ALL BEER.
THEN WE'LL DO OLD BAY.
DO ABOUT A HALF A CAN.
HALF A CAN?
ABOUT A HALF A CAN.
OKAY.
AND BRINGING IT BACK
TO A BOIL,
AND THEN WE'LL THROW
THE POTATOES IN.
SO IT'S A LITTLE BOIL.
JUST GRAB A POTATER
AND LOOK AT 'EM?
YEAH.
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
NOW WHAT GOES?
THE CORN.
THE SAUSAGE
IS ALREADY COOKED.
BUT YOU WANT IT
TO COOK A LITTLE BIT
TO BRING OUT
SOME OF THE FAT.
SO IT SEEPS THE FLAVOR
INTO THE BROTH.
WAIT TILL THAT COMES TO A BOIL.
THEN GO BACK WITH THE SHRIMP.
AS SOON AS THEY GO IN, YOU STIR
IT AROUND. THEY'RE DONE.
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH DONE.
AND YOU KEEP THE SHELL ON.
LOOK AT THAT MIXTURE.
KEEP THE SHELL ON.
MORE SOUP, PLEASE.
LOVE THE SMELL.
I LIKE OLD BAY ON ANYTHING.
JUST SMELL THAT.
I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD BE
LISTENING TO SOME JAZZ
OR SOME CAJUN MUSIC
RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S GREAT.
(whistles) WHOO!
SPICY?
YEAH!
(hoarse voice) VERY GENEROUS
WITH THE OLD BAY.
(laughs)
MMM! TENDER.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE CORN
WITH THE SPICINESS
WITH GETTING SOME
OF THAT ANDOUILLE IN THERE--
THAT IS EXCELLENT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S QUITE SPICY, WHICH I LIKE.
FOR A FOODIE WHO WANTS
TO STAY IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
THIS IS LIKE A DREAM.
AT A PLACE THAT'S BEEN
A NEIGHBORHOOD FIXTURE
SINCE THE LITTLE FAMILY
FIRST OPENED IT UP IN '29.
THEN SON LEON ADDED THE LUNCH
COUNTER IN THE EARLY '70s.
YOU TWO COME IN AND KIND
OF PULL THE LID OFF THINGS.
LEON WANTED TO RETIRE,
SO WE ASKED HIM
IF WE COULD TAKE OVER,
AND HE SAID YES.
AND WE PROMISED HIM WE'D KEEP
THE SAME GENERAL FEEL
AND UPDATE IT.
LIKE TOPPING A GRASS-FED BURGER
WITH SOUTHERN COMFORT FOOD...
HOW MANY PLACES
CAN YOU GO GET DELICIOUS
HOMEMADE PIMENTO CHEESE?
TAKING A CLASSIC
AND ADDING A TWIST.
I'VE HEARD OF CHICKEN
AND WAFFLES
DOWN HERE IN THE SOUTH,
BUT QUAIL?
THAT'S MY FIRST TIME
HEARING ABOUT IT, TOO.
QUAIL ON A WAFFLE?
MM-HMM.
GEORGIA QUAIL?
YES. WE SOAK IT
EVERY NIGHT IN BUTTERMILK
AND THEN ADD SOME EGGS TO
THE BUTTERMILK IN THE MORNING.
THE DREDGE WILL STICK
TO IT BETTER.
WHAT'S THE DREDGE?
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
CORNSTARCH, SALT AND PEPPER.
NOW DO YOU SHAKE OFF
THE EXCESS?
NOPE.
HOW WE LOOKING?
PRETTY GOOD.
I'M GONNA TURN IT OVER.
THE BIRD'S DONE?
IT LOOKS GOOD.
GREAT. LET'S MAKE
SOME WAFFLES.
YOU KIND OF HAVE
TO GET RID
OF YOUR NOTION OF WAFFLES
AT THIS POINT.
SO IT'S NOT
A BREAKFAST-Y THING.
THIS IS MORE LIKE
A MUFFIN OR A BREAD
OR SOMETHING THAT'S GOING
UNDERNEATH THIS.
EXACTLY.
EGGS IN HERE, BUTTERMILK,
AND THAT'S ABOUT 1/2 A CUP.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE HAVE
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR, CORNMEAL.
THIS IS BAKING POWDER.
THIS IS BAKING SODA.
MAKE IT SMOOTH.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO POUR?
JUST DO IT SLOWLY.
THAT BUTTER ON THE GRILL--
ABOUT A THIRD OF THE WAY.
DID YOU SAY A THIRD?
YEAH.
OR A HALF?
I SAID A THIRD.
I'LL JUST CHUG THE REST.
OKAY. AWESOME.
AND DOWN GOES THE BATTER?
YES.
HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?
THAT'S VERY NICE.
AND FOR THE SAUCE...
SCUPPERNONG JELLY?
THERE IT IS.
IS IT LIKE A GRAPE?
THEY'RE NOT AS SWEET.
DO THEY GROW WILD,
OR ARE THEY FARMED?
THEY'RE WILD.
DO YOU EVER PICK THESE?
UH-HUH. IT'S A VERY
TEDIOUS PROCESS.
SOUNDS LIKE FUN.
START THE SYRUP.
THAT IS
THE SCUPPERNONG JELLY.
OKAY, SO
THE SCUPPERNONG JELLY IS IN.
MMM. WHAT IS THAT?
EVERCLEAR?
A LITTLE BIT OF WINE.
WE'RE GONNA BRING THIS
TO A BOIL,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
THROW THESE GRAPES IN.
SO NOW THAT'S
GONNA REDUCE?
YES.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE QUAIL
ON THE WAFFLE FIRST.
LAY THEM
ON TOP OF EACH OTHER.
AND VOILà.
DOESN'T THAT LOOK GOOD?
YEAH.
WAFFLE IN ONE HAND
AND QUAIL IN THE OTHER?
YES.
MMM. I DIG IT.
I GET THE SALTY, SAVORY,
BUTTERINESS OF THE QUAIL.
NICE CRUNCH ON THE BATTER.
THAT'S GREAT...
BUT WEIRD...
BUT GREAT.
THE WAFFLE ISN'T AS SWEET
AS YOU WOULD HAVE EXPECTED.
KIND OF A NICE BALANCE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I WANT TO SEE WHAT
THEY COME UP WITH NEXT.
GREAT MIX OF HANDMADE
WITH MODERN TOUCHES.
A GOOD BREAK FROM FAST FOOD.
BUT THEY'VE GOT
THEIR OWN TAKE...
OKEYDOKEY.
ON THAT, TOO.
I LIKE THE CHEESEBURGER.
FROM THOSE BURGERS
TO SOUTHEAST ASIAN STYLE,
WHEN WE COME BACK.
HOW WAS IT?
IT WAS GREAT.
AT THE CABBAGETOWN MARKET
IN ATLANTA...
(Maria) YOU WANT TO JUST PUT
ALL OF THEM IN THERE?
LISA HANSON...
OKEYDOKEY.
AND MARIA LOCKE...
I'M GONNA BRING
YOU GUYS SOME QUAIL.
ARE DOING
SOME SERIOUS COOKING...
QUAIL ON A WAFFLE?
REALLY EXCELLENT.
AT WHAT USED TO BE
A BASIC LUNCH COUNTER,
AND IF ALL
YOU WANT'S A SANDWICH,
THEY'RE DOING THOSE
THEIR WAY, TOO...
MOZZARELLA?
AND BURGERS...
THAT GRASS-FED BEEF
IS A MAJOR DEAL?
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
OR THIS FAVORITE.
MEATBALL SANDWICH--
IT'S AWESOME.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
REALLY NICE
GOOD FLAVOR. GREAT.
I WOULDN'T DRIVE BY HERE
AND ANTICIPATE
THAT THE MEATBALL SANDWICH
WAS GONNA BE THAT ON POINT.
OR THAT THEY'RE ALSO DOING
A VIETNAMESE BANH MI SANDWICH
THAT MARIA FIRST DISCOVERED
ON A TRIP UP NORTH.
VIETNAMESE SANDWICH
MADE IN ATLANTA
BY A GIRL THAT HAD ONE
IN BROOKLYN.
MAKES SENSE? GOOD.
OKAY, GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'LL START
WITH THE MAYONNAISE
AND JUST GET THAT
OUT OF THE WAY.
OKAY.
TAKE THIS CHOPPED CILANTRO,
A LITTLE BIT OF HOT SAUCE.
MARRY SOME OF THOSE--
PUT CILANTRO FLAVOR INTO IT?
YEAH.
DIG IT. LET'S GO.
YOU CAN PUT YOUR SHALLOTS
AND YOUR LEMONGRASS.
AND YOU TAKE THAT FIRST
2 INCHES OFF THE BOTTOM,
PEEL OFF THE OUTER CORE
AND YOU PURéE IT.
YOU'RE IN IT TO WIN IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO YOU HAVE TO
PUT SOME OLIVE OIL IN HERE
AND SALT AND A LITTLE
BIT OF FISH SAUCE.
I LIKE TO GO LIKE THIS.
OH! THE EYE.
DO WE LOOK GOOD?
YEP.
MIX IT IN WITH THE PORK.
MAKE THEM PRETTY SMALL
SO THEY'LL FIT ON THE BAGUETTE.
LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE MEATBALL...
EXACTLY.
BUT FLAT AND MADE OUT
OF PORK ONLY...
MM-HMM.
AND ASIAN
AND NOT ITALIAN...
YES.
BUT JUST THE SAME,
BUT DIFFERENT.
THESE ARE GONNA
GO ON THE GRILL?
YES.
NOW THE BREAD
GOES IN THE OVEN?
YES.
I'M GONNA PUT THE MAYONNAISE
ON IT WITH THE BUTTER
BEFORE IT GOES IN THE OVEN.
REALLY?
YEAH.
BECAUSE?
BECAUSE IT TASTES GOOD.
A LITTLE
FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
IT'S THE ONLY TYPE OF PEPPER
TO USE, I THINK--FRESH CRACKED.
I KNOW.
I'M ADDICTED TO IT.
I PUT IT ON EVERYTHING.
LOOK AT THAT!
OKAY, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS SALAD.
CARROTS, THROW IN
JUST REGULAR RADISHES,
AND THEN A LITTLE
RICE WINE VINEGAR?
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
LOOK AT THAT.
(mumbles indistinctly)
WOW. I'M GETTING
ALL KINDS OF FLAVORS.
PICKLED VEGGIES
ARE, WITHOUT
A DOUBT, FANTASTIC.
THE PORK
IS NICE AND JUICY.
THAT CRAZY PUTTING THE MAYO
ON IN THE OVEN THING IS GREAT.
AND LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THAT PORK THERE
WITH ALL THOSE FLAVORS.
YOU WOULD SO LOVE THAT.
THAT WAS THE END
OF THE BANH MI SANDWICH?
THAT'S THE END OF IT.
YEAH. HOW WAS IT?
IT WAS GREAT. YEAH.
REALLY GOOD.
WE'LL BE BACK,
DEFINITELY.
THERE'S CLEARLY A LOT OF THOUGHT
INTO THE QUALITY OF THE FOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA GET SOMETHING
DIFFERENT EVERY TIME.
IT FITS THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN A LITTLE HUB
FOR THE COMMUNITY,
AND IT STILL IS.
IT'S A NICE JUXTAPOSITION.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF SURPRISES.
WE EXPERIMENT WITH STUFF,
AND IF PEOPLE KEEP ORDERING IT,
WE KEEP IT ON THE MENU.
SO YOU'RE SAYING THE AVERAGE
PERSON THAT COMES IN
IS SOMEWHAT
YOU'RE GUINEA PIG?
(laughs)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE D--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OKAY, IT'S NOT WORKING.
(imitates blender)
WHAT HAPPENED?
(making noises)
THAT'S ALL DONE.