HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
ORDER UP!
(bell dings)
(man) TAKIN' NUMBER ONE,
TWO AND THREE.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
IT'S BETTER
THAN HOME COOKIN'.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T
GO WRONG.
WHERE THE LOCALS EAT.
(woman) IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A WELL-KEPT SECRET.
IT'S A HOMETOWN
KIND OF PLACE.
RIGHT ON THE WATER IN
VIRGINIA...
THERE YOU GO.
WHERE A BOAT CAPTAIN...
THAT'S PRETTY.
TURNED COOK IS MAKING THE MOST
OF THE CHESAPEAKE BAY.
YOU ALWAYS KNOW YOU'RE ALWAYS
GETTING REALLY GOOD FRESH FISH.
WOW, YOU CAN REALLY
TASTE THE CRAB IN THAT.
GOOD CAKE, CAPTAIN.
ARGH.
IN MEMPHIS...
THAT'S HOME STYLE.
HOME STYLE.
WHERE THE CHICKEN'S FRIED...
IT'S FRESH, IT'S HOT
AND IT'S TASTY.
DIPPED...
THAT'S LIKE SWEET
SPICY LOVE.
AND DROPPED IN WHOLE.
YOU'RE CLOSE TO GETTIN'
HUGGED RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
LEAVE IT AT THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
AND IN OMAHA...
THERE YOU GO.
WHERE A WELL-TRAVELED CHEF...
EACH PLACE
HAS ITS OWN FLAVORS...
BROUGHT HIS RECIPES
BACK HOME.
AND THOSE THINGS ALL
MARRIED IN MY HEAD.
ECLECTIC WOULD BE THE BEST
WAY TO DESCRIBE IT.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
PLEASE TAKE THAT AWAY,
AND PUT IT IN THE RED CAR
OUT FRONT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, AROUND HERE
IN THE CHESAPEAKE BAY,
IT IS ALL ABOUT SEAFOOD,
AND THE PLACES YOU REALLY
WANT TO GO TO,
WELL, ONLY THE LOCALS KNOW,
AND THAT'S WHY I'M IN THIS
LITTLE FISHING VILLAGE
OF RESCUE, VIRGINIA,
TO CHECK OUT THIS JOINT.
CAPTAIN CHUCK-A-MUCK'S.
(woman) FIVE CAKES,
COMIN' UP.
ORDER UP!
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S PRETTY.
SO YOU'VE GOT LOCAL FOOD. A LOT
OF THIS FOOD IS CAUGHT HERE.
CRAB SOUP--ONE OF MY
FAVORITE THINGS HERE.
TONS OF GREAT FISH,
TONS OF GREAT SEAFOOD.
ORDER UP!
(bell dings)
WHEN YOU'VE GROWN UP
AROUND HERE,
HAVING FRESH FISH
IS REAL IMPORTANT.
YOU JUST DON'T WANT TO SETTLE
FOR ANYTHING ELSE.
AND SETTLING IS NO OPTION...
FRESH STRIPED BASS.
FOR THE GUY
RUNNING THIS JOINT.
HERE YOU GO.
I CALL HIM
CAPTAIN CHUCK.
CAPTAIN CHUCK!
YOU A CAPTAIN?
YEP.
REALLY?
THAT'S WHERE CAPTAIN
CHUCK-A-MUCK'S...
I'LL CUT AND GET IT
ALL READY FOR YOU.
CHUCK LAWRENCE SAYS HE WENT
FROM CAPTAIN TO COOK
KIND OF BY ACCIDENT.
(Chuck) I BOUGHT THE PROPERTY
FOR MY BOAT BUSINESS,
AND THIS LITTLE OLD LADY
HAD A SHACK.
THEY BOUGHT FRESH FISH,
OYSTERS, CRABS AND THAT TYPES
OF FRESH SEAFOOD
DOWN HERE.
FROM THE BOATING PEOPLE?
FROM THE BOAT, CAME
RIGHT UP OFF THE DOCK.
ORDER UP!
HE AND HIS WIFE CHRIS
DECIDED TO KEEP IT GOING
AND BUILD IT UP...
FIVE CAKES
AND SHRIMP.
AND A DECADE LATER,
THEY'VE BECOME A GO-TO JOINT
FOR A CROWD THAT GREW UP
ON THE WATER...
ORDER UP!
AND A LOCAL LEGEND FOR
A LOCAL FAVORITE--CRAB CAKES.
LOVE THE CRAB CAKE--
NOT MUCH FILLING,
VERY GOOD, TASTY.
ALL THRILLER,
NO FILLER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ONE OF OUR STAPLES.
IT REALLY IS ONE OF THE BIGGEST
THINGS THAT WE SELL.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO NOW?
EIGHT EGGS, YELLOW MUSTARD,
MAYONNAISE...
OLD BAY.
OLD BAY, A LITTLE SALT.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
AND WE'VE GOT SOME
FRESH PARSLEY
AND THEN A LITTLE
BLACK PEPPER.
GET IT ALL MIXED UP
REAL GOOD. GOT BREADCRUMBS.
ACTUALLY YOU WANT
TO SQUEEZE.
GOTTA HAVE A BINDING AGENT
ALONG WITH IT.
WOW. DON'T GO GETTING
ALL FOOD TV ON ME.
NOT REALLY.
"NOW I'M APPLYING
THE BINDING AGENT..."
OH, YES, YES, YES.
AS FAR AS CRABMEAT, WE USED
THREE DIFFERENT TYPES.
CLAW AND LEG.
RIGHT. LUMP,
AND THEN WE USE
THE JUMBO LUMP,
WHICH IS THE GREAT BIG BACK FIN
PIECES OF THE CRAB.
THAT'S HOW SHE GOES.
THIS IS REAL BUTTER.
RIGHT DOWN ON THE GRILL.
I GUESS HE'S NOT
HAVING ONE.
WHAT?
NOTHIN'!
THAT'S A MEAL
RIGHT THERE.
OH, YEAH.
GREAT COLOR, BIG PATTY.
I CAN SEE CRABMEAT.
FIRST THING THAT YOU LOOK
FOR IN A CRAB CAKE.
I DO.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT.
WOW, YOU CAN REALLY
TASTE THE CRAB IN THAT.
I'M REALLY PICKING UP
THE MUSTARD.
A LITTLE CRUNCH ON THE OUTSIDE.
GOOD CAKE, CAPTAIN.
AYE.
ARGH.
ALWAYS GET
THE CRAB CAKE SANDWICH,
EVEN IF IT'S NOTHIN'
BUT AN APPETIZER.
OR MAKE IT A MEAL...
THIS IS ALL CRAB.
OR YOU CAN HAVE YOUR CRAB CAKE
AS PART OF THE CAPTAIN'S
FRIED SEAFOOD FEAST.
THAT'S TOO MUCH FOOD
FOR ONE PERSON.
FLOUNDER, SCALLOPS,
SHRIMP,
OYSTERS, CRAB CAKE,
HUSH PUPPY.
MADE FRESH EVERY DAY.
MMM.
(Guy)
MMM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
THAT WAS GREAT.
THAT'S A GOOD HUSH PUPPY.
JUST THE WAY
I LIKE THEM.
BUT THE MAIN EVENT HERE
IS STILL THE SEAFOOD.
GOT A SHRIMP BOAT.
FOR GOOD REASON.
ORDER UP!
LOTS OF WATER
AROUND HERE,
SO TONS OF GREAT FISH,
TONS OF GREAT SEAFOOD.
IT'S JONES CREEK.
THIS LEADS RIGHT OUT...
THAT'S A BIG CREEK.
TO THE JAMES RIVER,
AND THEN THE JAMES RIVER LEADS
RIGHT OUT OT THE CHESAPEAKE BAY.
CHUCK HAS A CONNECTION
WITH A LOT OF THE GUYS
THAT OWN FISHING BOATS.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE ALWAYS GETTING
REALLY GOOD, FRESH FISH.
WHAT DO YOU GOT
FOR ME TODAY?
IF THEY'RE NOT LOCAL
OR IN SEASON AROUND HERE,
CHUCK STILL KNOWS
WHERE TO FIND 'EM.
I NEED SIX SHRIMPS
IN THE STEAMER.
WE WERE BUYING FRESH
NORTH CAROLINA SHRIMP
THAT WE WERE GETTING IN
EVERY WEEK.
(Guy) HOW INCREDIBLE
IS THE FLAVOR ON THAT?
OH, YEAH.
WHAT KIND OF SEASONING
IS ON THERE?
CAPTAIN CHUCK'S
SECRET, I'M SURE.
CHUCK'S DOING
FRESH YELLOWFIN TUNA,
STRIPED BASS,
ATLANTIC FLOUNDER,
EVEN THE OLD SURF AND TURF.
WHERE DO THEY
CATCH THE STEAK?
GOOD QUESTION.
BUT THE BIGGEST DRAW
FOR A LOT OF FOLKS...
A HOMETOWN
KIND OF PLACE.
IS COOKIN'
CHESAPEAKE BAY STYLE.
PHENOMENAL.
CHUCK'S TAKE...
MMM.
ON SHE-CRAB SOUP.
THIS IS SO GOOD.
SHE-CRAB BASICALLY USES ROE--
THE EGG PORTIONS
OF A FEMALE CRAB.
NOW DO YOU GET A CAVIAR-Y
POP FROM IT?
IT IS DEFINITELY
DISTINCTIVE.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
HOW DO WE GET HER STARTED?
WE REALLY LIKE
THE BACON.
A STICK OF BUTTER.
THEN WE COME OVER
WITH OUR VEGETABLES--
ONIONS, CELERY...
AND THE BELL PEPPERS.
AND THEN BELL PEPPERS.
I'M IMPRESSED.
IT'S ALL I GOT.
I'M A 1-TRICK PONY.
MAGIC ELIXIR--
OLD BAY SEASONING.
LET'S DO THE CRAB ROE.
SPRINKLE THAT.
GONNA PUT A LITTLE
CHICKEN STOCK,
A LITTLE SHERRY,
WORCESTERSHIRE.
OH, SMELLS FANTASTIC.
AND NOW THE BASE IS DONE.
BASE IS DONE.
YOU'VE GOT YOURSELF A, UH--
CREAM SOUP BASE.
JUST GONNA JOIN THIS IN.
IT'S VERY THICK.
OH, YEAH.
AND THE SAME THREE KINDS
OF CRAB THAT CHUCK USES
IN HIS CRAB CAKE.
THREE DIFFERENT TEXTURES
AS FAR AS CRABMEAT.
WE USE A LOT OF IT AS FAR
AS OUR SOUP IS CONCERNED.
HALF-AND-HALF?
HALF-AND-HALF.
THEN WE JUST PUT THIS
UP ON HERE.
THAT'S ONE HI-DE-HO.
PRETTY THICK SAUCE
THERE, CAPTAIN.
IT'S A HEARTY SOUP.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT IF YOU'RE
HUNGRY, YOU'RE HUNGRY...
YOU JUST GO AFTER THIS.
(Chuck) THIS IS JUST
REGULAR SHERRY
THAT WE JUST KIND OF
GET THAT LITTLE
TASTE GOING.
MMM.
THAT'S RICH.
I LIKE THE CREAMINESS
OF IT.
THERE'S MORE CRAB IN THERE
THAN I'VE EVER SEEN ANY CLAMS
IN CLAM CHOWDER.
THAT'S A LOT.
THIS IS GOOD.
IT'S JUST A GOOD SOUP.
THE SECOND TASTE
IS AS GOOD AS THE FIRST.
JUST ONE OF THE REASONS
THE LOCALS KEEP COMIN' BACK.
SHRIMP. ARE THEY YUMMY?
THEY LOOK YUMMY.
SO WHAT LOOKS GOOD?
GREAT PLACE
TO GO, MAN.
(Guy) THIS IS IT?
VERY COZY.
THIS IS THE THING OUT HERE.
ONCE YOU COME IN, YOU JUST
FALL IN LOVE WITH THE PLACE.
YOU WON'T RUN AMOK
WHEN YOU HANG WITH CHUCK.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
UP NEXT...
HOW'S IT GOIN', GUYS?
WE'RE HEADING FOR MEMPHIS...
YOU ALWAYS COME BACK
TO UNCLE LOU'S.
WHERE THEY'RE LINING UP
FOR GREAT GRANDMA'S CHICKEN...
HOW DOES THIS RATE?
RIGHT AT THE VERY TOP.
DONE UNCLE LOU'S WAY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT.
WON'T MAKE YOUR HAIR
STAND ON END.
JUST LET--
YOU KNOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
HOW I LIKE TO FIND THE FUNKIEST
JOINTS IN TOWN?
WELL, I FOUND ONE
HERE IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE,
IN THIS STRIP MALL
BY THE AIRPORT.
IT'S A PLACE CALLED UNCLE LOU'S,
AND HE'S DOING CHICKEN
ONE OF MY FAVORITE WAYS--
FRIED AND DIPPED.
OH.
TAKIN' NUMBER ONE,
TWO AND THREE.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE
TO GET CHICKEN.
MAKE YOUR TONGUE
SLAP YOUR BRAINS OUT.
THANKS FOR CALLIN'
UNCLE LOU'S.
YEAH, WE GOT THE HONEY-DIPPED,
THE HOME-STYLE.
THESE ARE THE SPICY.
ONE MORE.
YOU ALWAYS COME BACK
TO UNCLE LOU'S.
MAN!
IN THE WORLD OF CHICKEN,
HOW DOES THIS RATE?
RIGHT AT THE VERY TOP.
IT'S AWESOME. IT'S BETTER
THAN HOME COOKIN'.
UNCLE LOU!
IT'S UNCLE LOU'S
HOME COOKING.
I'VE KIND OF BEEN COOKING
JUST ABOUT ALL MY LIFE.
ALL RIGHTY,
AN 8-PIECE.
A FEW YEARS AGO...
YOU DOIN' ALL RIGHT?
LOUIS MARTIN
OPENED HIS OWN JOINT...
WHAT WE GOT
GOIN' NOW?
DOING CHICKEN THE WAY
HIS GREAT-GRANDMOTHER DID...
CAN YOU GET ALL THIS OUT
BY YOURSELF?
AND FOLKS JUST WENT NUTS.
I DROVE 30 MILES
TO COME EAT HERE.
NO KIDDING?
THAT'S HOW GOOD IT IS.
THE CHICKEN AND THE SAUCE.
YOU'VE GOTTA TRY THIS.
THIS IS BANANAS...
AND BANANAS IS GOOD. YOU KNOW
THAT, THOUGH, DON'T YOU?
AND GET THIS--
HE'S EVEN FRYING IT WHOLE.
OH, MY GOSH.
AND THE CROWD...
HOW Y'ALL DOIN'?
KEEPS PACKING IN.
HOW'S IT GOIN', GUYS?
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
SOUTHERN CHICKEN.
JUST EATING--GREASY HANDS
AND EVERYTHING.
THIS CHICKEN IS FRESH,
IT'S HOT, AND IT'S TASTY.
NOW WHO MADE
THIS RECIPE?
THE BASIS CAME
FROM MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR. SEEMS LIKE
QUITE A BIT, DOESN'T IT?
BLACK PEPPER.
WHAT IS THIS A RATIO OF,
TWO TO ONE?
CLOSER TO LIKE
THREE TO ONE.
A LITTLE SALT,
GOT A LITTLE ONION,
A LITTLE GARLIC.
GUESS WHAT THE OTHER ONE IS.
CINNAMON.
HEY.
IS IT CINNAMON?
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
THAT IS A FIRST.
OKAY, SO WE JUST DREDGE--
SO THIS DOESN'T GO
IN A WASH OR ANYTHING?
NO.
THIS IS HOW YOUR
GRANDMOTHER DID IT?
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER.
YOU DREDGE IT
IN THE MIXTURE TO ORDER?
WE DO.
COOKED TO ORDER.
SHAKE THE EXCESS OFF, 'CAUSE WE
LIKE TO HAVE A LIGHT COATING.
THIGH FIRST, THEN THE DRUM,
THEN THE BREAST--
WING.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA GO WING,
THEN THE BREAST?
SO THAT BREAST IS EVEN
GONNA COOK FASTER
THAN THAT LITTLE
WING DING.
BINGO.
THEN WE PLAY BINGO.
12 MINUTES. LET ME SET
THE TIMER HERE.
GOOD GOLDEN BROWN.
HEY, GUESS WHO'S DUMB ENOUGH TO
TAKE A BITE OF THAT RIGHT NOW?
NOBODY.
EVIDENTLY, YOU HAVEN'T
SEEN THE SHOW.
THAT'S HOME-STYLE.
HOME-STYLE.
THAT'S GOOD.
THANK YOU.
GOOD CRUNCH.
THAT'S WHY WE DON'T
DO THE EGG WASH.
YOU COOK THAT CHICKEN SKIN--
THAT'S THAT CRUNCHY CHICKEN SKIN
THAT PEOPLE LIKE.
I CAN HEAR THAT SAUCE
CALLING MY NAME.
IT HAS TO BE SOMETHING SPECIAL
HE PUTS IN THE SAUCE.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY CHICKEN
I'VE EVER HAD ANYWHERE ELSE.
IS IT LIKE
A BARBECUE SAUCE?
NO, IT'S MORE LIKE
A BUFFALO WING SAUCE.
WHO'S RECIPE IS THIS?
THIS ONE IS MINE.
THIS IS YOURS.
RED WINE VINEGAR.
LOUISIANA CAJUN CHEF.
WE'RE STILL IN TENNESSEE,
THOUGH, RIGHT?
WE'RE STILL IN TENNESSEE.
NOW WHAT ARE WE ADDING?
THE SPICES
ARE GONNA GO IN.
GARLIC, CHILI POWDER--A CUP.
WOW, CHILI POWDER.
WOW. SALT.
MMM, I LOVE PAPRIKA.
YEAH, PAPRIKA.
IT'S GOTTA BE ONION.
CELERY SALT.
THAT'S THE SUGAR.
LEMON PEPPER.
SMOKE?
HICKORY SMOKE.
(whistles)
ALL RIGHTY.
THIS IS CALLED CORRUPTION.
IT'S CALLED THE CORRUPTION?
CORRUPTION.
ONCE YOU'VE TASTED IT,
YOU'VE BEEN CORRUPTED.
REALLY?
BINGO.
BINGO!
IN?
IN. AS SOON AS IT
COMES TO A BOIL,
TRY TO GET THE CORRUPTION IN
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT
THE VINEGAR TO EVAPORATE.
NOW WHEN'S THE HONEY
GO IN?
RIGHT NOW.
WE TURN UP THE HEAT...
AND THEN WE DUMP
THE HONEY.
HONEY DIP SAUCE...
YEAH?
COMPLETE.
OH.
DIFFERENT.
NO--MONEY. THAT'S LIKE
SWEET SPICY LOVE.
NOTED. NAME CHANGE.
NO LONGER HONEY DIP SAUCE--
(both) SWEET, SPICY LOVE.
IT'S GONNA GO IN OUR SAUCE?
DO WE LADLE OVER--
WE CALL IT HONEY DIP,
NOT HONEY LADLE.
THAT'S IT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
WOW, MAN.
YOU'RE CLOSE TO GETTING
A HUG RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
LEAVE IT AT THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GET THE VINEGAR,
BACKS UP WITH THE SWEETNESS...
AND JUST A LITTLE HEAT.
WANT A LITTLE MORE HEAT?
I GOTTA TRY MORE SPICY.
NO PROBLEM.
UNCLE LOU'S GOT THAT, TOO.
WE HAVE A LESS SPICY
AND A MORE SPICY.
YOU JUST HAVE SPICY?
SPICY IS THE LESS SPICY.
YOU'VE GOTTA START
WITH THE SPICY?
RIGHT, AND THEN WE MADE
A MORE SPICY,
WHICH MADE THE ORIGINAL SPICY
LESS SPICY.
DID I JUST BUY
THAT STREET?
HOW DO WE MAKE IT
MORE SPICY?
200 HEAT
CAYENNE PEPPER.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT.
JUST HOT ENOUGH
TO MAKE YOU THIRSTY.
WON'T MAKE YOUR HAIR
STAND ON END.
JUST LET--
(mumbling)
EXACTLY.
I KNEW YOU UNDERSTOOD.
AND UNCLE LOU
IS NO 1-HIT WONDER.
TWO JUMBO
CHEESEBURGERS.
FOLKS ARE LOVING
WHATEVER HE'S COOKING...
MMM.
LIKE HONEY-DIPPED
FRIED BOLOGNA.
LOOK AT THAT.
IF I SAY GOOD,
IT IS GOOD.
AND A DIPPED
SMOKED SAUSAGE SANDWICH.
JUST SOAKS IN THE BREAD,
AND IT'S GREAT.
A JUMBO CHEESEBURGER.
IT'S JUST THE CHEESEBURGER
TO HAVE.
HE MAKES A REAL GOOD
MONSTER BURGER HERE.
BUT EVEN WITH ALL THAT...
STUFF GETS BETTER
EVERY TIME I EAT HERE.
THE NAME IS STILL
UNCLE LOU'S FRIED CHICKEN,
AND HE'S TAKING IT
TO THE MAX.
WHOLE FRIED CHICKEN?
THAT'S OUR SIGNATURE ITEM.
I CAN SIGN WITH THAT.
MUST MAKE A MESS
ON PAPER.
SO WHAT DO YOU
INJECT THE BIRD?
CAJUN CREOLE BUTTER.
LIKE SOMETHING YOU BUY?
SO YOU MOVE IT AROUND
A LITTLE BIT. THERE YOU GO.
BUT YOU DON'T
GO THROUGH THE SKIN,
BECAUSE THEN IT COULD
HAVE A CHANCE TO LEAK.
NOW YOU HAVE TO BE A LITTLE BIT
CHOOSY ABOUT THE MARINADE YOU DO
BECAUSE IF IT'S GOT A BUNCH OF
SUGAR IN IT, IT'LL BURN THE OIL.
EXACTLY.
LEGS AND THIGHS FIRST.
40 MINUTES?
40 MINUTES.
YOU GONNA DUNK IT
OR SERVE IT--
WE GONNA DUNK IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS THE MAGIC.
THE CORRUPTION.
BY THE WAY, I AM TAKING
THE CORRUPTION HOME WITH ME.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, MY GOSH.
YOU CAN REALLY PICK UP
THE FLAVOR OF THAT
GARLIC BUTTER.
YOU REALLY DON'T
NEED A KNIFE.
MMM. LOOK HOW TENDER
AND JUICY THAT IS.
AND THAT'S IT--
IT'S NOT REALLY OILY.
I THINK PEOPLE THINK,
OH, YOU FRIED IT,
IT'S GOTTA BE ALL OILY.
TAKE OUR FIRST FAMILY PHOTO.
LOOKS LIKE US, DOESN'T IT.
YOU'RE OFF THE CHAIN, MAN,
I GOTTA TELL YOU.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
THIS IS LIKE
REAL CHICKEN.
OH, IT'S NICE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OH, IT IS,
IT'S VERY GOOD CHICKEN.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
HOT WINGS HERE ARE GREAT.
MAMA DOESN'T EVEN COOK IT
BETTER THAN THAT.
YOU EVER HAD THIS CHICKEN?
IT'S CRAZY.
YOU GOT A LOT
TO BE PROUD OF.
THANK YOU.
IF YOU LIVE WITHIN
300 MILES OF THIS JOINT...
MM-HMM.
YOU SHOULD BE GETTING YOURSELF
OVER HERE RIGHT QUICK NOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'D DO?
WHAT?
CHICKEN'S FREE.
NAPKINS ARE 500 BUCKS EACH.
UP NEXT...
AND THERE YOU GO.
OMAHA...
THIS IS REAL FOOD.
I KNOW I'M ALWAYS
GONNA GET SOMETHING GREAT.
AT A PLACE YOU CAN DRIVE
RIGHT BY...
YOU KNOW,
THERE'S NO SIGN.
BUT THAT'S WHY
WE LIKE IT.
SO YOU GOTTA BE
IN THE KNOW?
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S SHAMA LAMA
PUTS IT IN THE DING DONG,
OR IF THIS IS THE OOH
IN THE MOW-MOW.
NOW ONE OF THE THINGS YOU'VE
LEARNED HERE ON TRIPLE D
IS TO SLOW IT DOWN
AND KEEP YOUR EYES PEELED,
'CAUSE YOU WOULDN'T WANT
TO CRUISE BY A JOINT
YOU NEVER NOTICED
BUT YOU DIDN'T WANT TO MISS,
LIKE HERE ON LEAVENWORTH STREET
THAT HEADS INTO
DOWNTOWN OMAHA, NEBRASKA.
YOU GOTTA COME CHECK OUT
DIXIE QUICKS.
YOU COULD DRIVE
PAST IT,
AND YOU WOULDN'T EVEN
KNOW IT WAS HERE.
PICADILLO.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NO SIGN.
BUT THAT'S WHY
WE LIKE IT.
SO YOU GOTTA BE
IN THE KNOW?
YOU GOT IT.
BUT ONCE YOU FIND IT...
IT'S GOOD.
THERE'S A MENU FULL OF REASONS
TO KEEP COMING BACK.
(man) ENJOY.
IT'S PROBABLY THE BEST
IN THE CITY.
ECLECTIC WOULD BE
THE BEST WAY TO DESCRIBE IT.
CACTUS AND EGGS.
MIXED BERRY FRENCH TOAST.
STACKED WITH BERRIES
AND WHIPPED CREAM.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
CHICKEN TORTILLA SOUP.
IT'S FLAVORFUL
AND DELICIOUS.
THIS IS REAL FOOD.
OKAY.
DONE BY A REAL
SERIOUS CHEF--
RENé ORDUÑA.
HE CAN COOK
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
PICADILLO UP ON TOP.
'CAUSE HE COOKED
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY...
TWO FRENCH TOAST ON.
BEFORE COMING BACK TO OMAHA
WHERE HE STARTED OUT IN HIS
PARENTS' MEXICAN RESTAURANT.
YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF CAJUN,
OF COSMOPOLITAN, LATINO.
HE HAS A REAL SIMPLE WAY
OF PUTTING WONDERFUL
FLAVORS TOGETHER.
I KNOW I'M ALWAYS GONNA
GET SOMETHING GREAT
AND SOMETHING UNIQUE.
TEXAS CHILI PEPPER STEAK.
MM-HMM.
IT'S GOT PEPPERS
AND ONIONS,
AND IT'S LAYING ON THIS
AWESOME BED OF MASHED POTATOES.
IT'S SO GOOD.
SO THIS IS LIKE A TAKEOFF
ON THE STEAK AU POIVRE--
PEPPER STEAK.
THAT TYPICALLY HAS PEPPERCORNS
AND BRANDY IN A CREAM SAUCE.
UH-HUH, WHERE THIS IS JUST
TAKING IT A LITTLE BIT FURTHER.
WE ADD CHILI PEPPERS--
THE ANAHEIMS, JALEPEÑOS
AND POBLANO PEPPERS.
YOU HAD ME AT HELLO
ON THAT.
GOT A NEW YORK STRIP.
(whistles)
YOU GET
ABOUT A 10-OUNCE.
WELCOME TO OMAHA. IT'S LIKE
A BUSINESS CARD IN OMAHA.
HERE YOU GO. CALL ME.
(laughing)
WOW, YOU REALLY TRIM IT.
JUST A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER.
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER
IN THE PAN.
STEAK GOING IN THE PAN.
GOOD LITTLE SIZZLE GOING.
WE GOT SOME RED ONION,
ANAHEIM, JALAPEÑOS, POBLANOS.
WELCOME TO SPEED COOKING
WITH RENé.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
SAUTé 'EM FOR JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THROW THE BOURBON ON.
UNCLE RENé,
WHERE'S THE MARSHMALLOWS?
A LITTLE BEEF STOCK
ADDED TO THAT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE STEAK OUT
FOR A MINUTE.
'CAUSE YOU DON'T WANT
TO OVERCOOK IT AND BOIL IT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON THE FLAT TOP
JUST TO GET A NICE
LITTLE SEAR ON IT.
LIKE YOU WEREN'T BUILT
FOR TELEVISION CHEF-ING.
LET THIS REDUCE DOWN.
WE'LL ADD THE CREAM NOW.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
EAT THAT WITH?
A LITTLE MASHED POTATOES.
OUR STEAK IS DEFINITELY
A NICE MEDIUM RARE.
THROW THAT ON HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. OH.
YOU NEED ANOTHER BITE.
THAT'S BANANAS.
THAT PEPPER--THE TRIO.
THE JALAPEÑO'S
NOT OVERPOWERING,
AND THE WHISKEY
AND THE CREAM.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S SHAMA LAMA
PUTS IT IN THE DING DONG,
OR IF THIS IS THE OOH
IN THE MOW-MOW.
OUT OF THE TOP PEPPER STEAKS
I'VE EVER HAD,
THAT'S GOTTA BE
IN THE TOP THREE.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT SORT OF MELTS IN MY MOUTH.
(man) VERY GOOD.
VERY TASTY.
EVERY PLATE
IS VERY GOOD.
YOU CAN JUST HAVE
AMAZING FOOD EVERY TIME.
AND IT CAN COME FROM
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE...
THANK YOU.
'CAUSE RENé'S
PROBABLY BEEN THERE.
NEW YORK...
ATLANTA.
SAN FRANCISCO.
NEW ORLEANS.
KANSAS CITY.
PLATES OVER
TO THIS SIDE.
EACH PLACE HAS
ITS OWN FLAVORS,
AND THOSE THINGS
ALL MARRIED IN MY HEAD.
BLACKENED SALMON.
LIKE SOME LOUISIANA COOKING
HE LEARNED FROM
A CHEF IN NEW YORK.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT'S IN
THE BLACKENED SEASONING,
BUT IT'S REALLY GOOD.
CAJUN SEASONING,
PICKLING SPICE.
THIS IS MY MIXTURE.
ADDS TO THAT CHILI FLAVOR.
WOW. YOU LITTLE
WIZARD, YOU.
SAGE.
SALT AND PEPPER, GARLIC.
CHILI FLAKE.
CUMIN. WE GOT
ALL THE MIXTURE DONE.
NOW WE GOTTA CUT
A LITTLE SALMON FOR IT.
I KNOW I USE A NICE SALMON
FILLET. YOU TAKE THE SPICE...
A LITTLE DREDGE.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO TASTE THIS SPICE.
SO IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
GIVE YOU A NICE LITTLE BURST OF
FLAVOR EVERY TIME YOU BITE IT.
ALL THREE OF 'EM? WHAT IS THIS
LITTLE CONCOCTION HERE?
THAT'S CALLED
TOMATO BUTTER.
IT'S EQUAL PARTS UNSALTED
BUTTER, IT'S TOMATOES,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
PARSLEY AND SALT AND PEPPER,
AND I MAKE IT ON
THE CAPPUCCINO MACHINE--
STEAMER, ACTUALLY--PART OF
THE CAPPUCCINO MACHINE.
REALLY?
OKAY, LOOK AT THAT.
WE MIGHT BE IN OMAHA,
BUT HE COOKS SALMON LIKE
HE'S ON THE PACIFIC COAST.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
NOW YOU NEED TO DUMP IT IN
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT BUTTER.
WOW, DUDE.
IT'S NOT OVER-BLACKENED.
NO.
I WOULD ORDER THAT ONCE A WEEK.
AND I ALMOST DROVE BY.
BIGGEST MISTAKE
I WOULD HAVE MADE.
FUNKY LITTLE JOINT,
ECLECTIC MIX OF PEOPLE,
AND THIS IS WHAT I'M FINDING
BACK HERE.
HE'S LIKE THE WIZARD OF OZ.
IT'S NOT KANSAS.
BUT HOW ABOUT MEXICO?
IT'S DOWN-HOME COOKING.
'CAUSE AFTER GROWING UP
WITH MEXICAN COOKING,
RENé IS DOING THAT
HIS OWN WAY, TOO...
ALMOST LIKE A HOT
PICO de GALLO CHICKEN SOUP.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
DIXIE QUICKS
IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA,
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE MUCH
FROM THE OUTSIDE...
WE NEED FOUR OF THEM.
BUT INSIDE, CHEF AND CO-OWNER
RENé ORDUÑA...
FRENCH TOAST.
IS DOING SERIOUS FOOD
FROM ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
MMM.
IF YOU DON'T TRY THAT,
YOU'RE MAKING A MISTAKE.
(man) QUESO FRESCO.
AND RENé'S DOING HIS OWN TAKE
ON ALL KINDS
OF MEXICAN DISHES, TOO.
ZUCCHINI AND CHEESE--
A DISH MY MOTHER
TAUGHT ME HOW TO MAKE.
PICADILLO.
A TRADITIONAL
MEXICAN BEEF STEW.
MMM.
REALLY RICH.
THAT'S GOOD.
IT HAS A REALLY GOOD
MEDLEY OF FLAVORS.
MMM.
YOU KNOW,
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
THE FOOD IS HOME-STYLE FOOD.
LIKE RENé'S OWN TAKE
ON A TRADITIONAL MEXICAN SOUP--
CHICKEN TORTILLA.
IT'S A GREAT SOUP.
THE FIRST THING YOU TASTE IS
HOW FRESH THE INGREDIENTS ARE.
WE'RE MAKING
PICO de GALLO.
THIS IS GOING INTO
THE CHICKEN TORTILLA SOUP.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA DO THE ONION,
ZUCCHINI AND YELLOW SQUASH.
SEE, I THINK THIS IS NEAT
WITH THE SQUASH,
THROWING SOME VERY
INTERESTING TEXTURE IN THERE.
AND AS WE GET MORE
AND MORE VEGETABLES
AS THE SUMMER ROLLS ON...
KEEP KNOCKIN'
IT OUT, YEAH.
WE ADD A LITTLE MORE OF THAT,
A LITTLE MORE,
AND IT GETS NICER AND NICER.
NOW WE GOT THE PEPPERS--
THE POBLANOS, ANAHEIMS...
ANAHEIMS.
AND JALAPEÑO.
AND THE CILANTRO, RIGHT?
THEY JUST ALL GO TOGETHER.
CHICKEN STOCK TO START OFF.
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
AND TOMATO JUICE
FROM THE TOMATOES
WE MADE THE PICO WITH.
V8 JUICE, AND THAT ADDS A LITTLE
BIT MORE OF THE TOMATO--
A LITTLE BIT MORE
VEGETABLE.
THEN WE ADD OUR POTATOES,
OUR CHICKEN,
WHICH IS NICELY CHOPPED,
AND NOW THAT PICO.
WE GOT A LITTLE MORE CILANTRO,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
THAT'S GONNA SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
IT DOESN'T TAKE
VERY LONG AT ALL.
I LIKE THE CONFETTI
OF THE ONIONS
AND THE SQUASH IN THERE.
THAT REALLY LOOKS NICE.
THEN ON TOP OF THAT, GOT A FEW
CHIPS AND A LITTLE AVOCADO.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
THE FLAVOR IS SO FRESH.
ALMOST LIKE A HOT
PICO de GALLO CHICKEN SOUP.
I MEAN, IT'S JUST--IT'S NOT
ONE THING, IT'S MULTIPLE.
OH, IT'S GOOD, MAN.
EVERY DAY
THAT'S ON THE MENU?
THAT'S ON THE MENU.
WE MAKE ENOUGH
FOR ONE DAY.
IT DOESN'T SIT AROUND,
AND WHATEVER GOES, GOES.
YEAH, SO IF IT'S DONE,
IT'S DONE.
YOU ORDER SOMETHIN' ELSE.
SO IF YOU WANT TO WIN
HERE AT THE DIXIE QUICKS,
YOU BETTER GET HERE EARLY.
IT'S JUST THAT
FRESH GARDEN TASTE
ALONG WITH THE SPICINESS.
CONSISTENTLY DELICIOUS.
AMAZING FOOD
EVERY TIME.
I WANT THEM TO HAVE THE BEST
FOOD THEY'VE HAD IN A LONG TIME.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU ORDER,
YOU KNOW IT'S ALWAYS
GOING TO BE VERY SPECIAL.
YOU'RE A FANTASTIC
CHEF, MAN.
IS IT OKAY TO PICK
OFF PEOPLE'S PLATE?
WELL, IT'S NICE
IF YOU ASK, BUT...
IS THAT--
DID YOU DROP THAT?
NICE. YOU WERE IN ON IT, TOO.
I LIKED IT.
YOU LIKE THAT, HUH?
'CAUSE YOU GAVE THE...
THE GLANCE.
SO IS THAT A MONEY
ROAD TRIP, OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHY COULDN'T LESS SPICY
BE SPICY,
MORE SPICY BE MORE SPICY
THAN THE SPICY,
BUT HOME-STYLE
BE THE NON-SPICY,
SO SPICY, LESS SPICY
IS THE MIDDLE?
I FEEL LIKE I JUST
BOUGHT THE STREET.