HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
THIS TRIP...
ORDER UP. PEPPERS, NO ONIONS.
GRABBING A SANDWICH.
ARMS OUT. MMM.
CHILI, MUSHROOMS, PEPPERS.
DELI FAVORITES...
IT'S SO GOOD.
IN SALT LAKE CITY...
I'D NEVER HAD A PHILLY
CHEESESTEAK BEFORE COMING HERE.
I'M HOOKED.
AND MASSIVE MEATBALLS.
MMM.
YOU GOT TO TRY THAT.
IN SAN DIEGO...
THIS IS FABULOUS.
THE AMERICAN CLASSIC
WITH A TWIST...
THEY HAVE OSTRICH.
KANGAROO BURGER.
KANGAROO RARE.
THAT'S CRAZY!
SERVED BY A COUPLE OF GUYS
FROM GERMANY.
SAUERKRAUT AND POTATO SALAD.
BEST BURGERS IN TOWN.
CRAZY BITE.
THIS IS GETTING
OUT OF CONTROL.
AND IN CHICAGO...
IT'S EXCELLENT. IT'S SO GOOD.
SOMETHING CALLED A CEMITA...
THIS IS UNIQUE.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF IT.
YOU ALMOST NEVER FIND OUTSIDE
OF ONE MEXICAN CITY.
DELICIOUS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M CRUISING
SALT LAKE CITY, UTAH,
AND I'VE GOT A HANKERING
FOR SOME PHILLY FOOD,
YOU KNOW, PHILLY CHEESESTEAKS,
MEATBALL SUBS.
THE ONLY PROBLEM I GOT
IS I'M 2,100 MILES AWAY
FROM PHILLY.
WELL, PEOPLE AROUND HERE SAY,
"DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
ALL YOU GOT TO DO
IS CHECK OUT MOOCHIES."
(man) PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
I'D NEVER HAD A PHILLY
CHEESESTEAK BEFORE COMING HERE.
AND I'M HOOKED.
IT'S THE DRIP.
IT'S THE MESS.
SEE THE RUNOFF?
YEAH.
I GET THE 12-INCH EVERY TIME.
ORDER UP!
MEATBALL PROV.
IT'S PHILADELPHIA-STYLE FOOD.
HERE YOU GO.
FROM PHILLY NATIVE
JOANNA RENDI...
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
THANKS, MOOCHIE.
NICKNAMED "MOOCHIE" BY HER DAD
AND RAISED ON
THIS PHILLY CLASSIC.
I'M FROM A PHILLY.
I KNOW WHAT A CHEESESTEAK IS.
I KNOW WHAT THE DEAL IS.
OR WAS, 'CAUSE WHEN SHE MOVED
TO SALT LAKE CITY,
SHE COULDN'T FIND A REAL ONE.
(Joanna) THEY DIDN'T HAVE
A GOOD SANDWICH SHOP.
SO SHE OPENED ONE...
12-INCH,
PEPPERS, EXTRA ONIONS.
IN HER HUSBAND DON MacDONALD'S
POTTERY SHOP.
HEY, LET'S PUT
IN A KITCHEN.
SO ANYTHING YOU ATE AS A KID
YOU GOT ON THE MENU.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW THE POTTERY'S
STILL FOR SALE...
PHILLY, MUSHROOMS, PEPPERS.
BUT THE SANDWICH BUSINESS
HAS TAKEN OFF.
MMM. IT'S SO GOOD.
GREAT FLAVORS, THE MEAT
IS JUST RIGHT, JUST FANTASTIC.
WE'RE GONNA
PLATE FOOD TODAY.
SO THIS IS OUR
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK GRIDDLE.
LITTLE OIL.
GET SOME ONIONS DOWN.
LITTLE SALT.
YOU GOT SOME...
VERY THIN-SLICED
RIB-EYE STEAK.
OKAY, THESE ARE RED
AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
AND THEN
SOME SHROOMS HERE.
OKAY, SO PROCESSED AMERICAN.
AND OUR CRISPY ROLLS.
NOW THIS RIGHT HERE, FOLKS,
THIS IS HOW YOU SEE IT DONE.
YOU WARM THAT BREAD UP
BY STEAMING IT ON TOP OF THERE.
THIS GUY'S LEGIT.
YOU JUST WANT TO GET
THAT CHEESE MELTING IN THERE.
OH, YEAH. YEAH.
MMM. WOW.
MMM.
THE MEAT'S SUPER TENDER.
MMM. THE PEPPERS,
COOKED A LITTLE BIT,
SO THEY'RE BROKEN DOWN.
RIGHT.
AND THAT RIGHT THERE,
THAT'S THE GOODNESS.
YOU CAN'T EAT IT FAST ENOUGH.
THE MEAT'S REALLY TENDER.
THE CHEESE IS GREAT.
AND YOU GET IT HOW YOU LIKE IT.
OKAY, PEPPERS, NO ONION.
WITH ONIONS, PEPPERS,
MUSHROOMS,
EVEN MOOCHIE'S
HOMEMADE MARINARA.
THE MARINARA SAUCE
ACTUALLY BRINGS IT ALL TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME MARINARA SAUCE.
WE'LL START WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
SO A LITTLE GARLIC.
GARLIC AND SOME ONION.
AND WE'RE GONNA SIT THERE
AND SWEAT THIS?
MM-HMM.
I'LL PUT MY SALT
AND PEPPER IN.
FRESH ROASTED RED PEPPERS.
AND WE DO THESE IN-HOUSE.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO DO IT.
THEN I'M GONNA CHOP UP
SOME FRESH HERBS.
YOU FROZE THESE?
YEAH, IT MAKES IT EASIER
TO CHOP 'EM THAT WAY.
THIS IS A TRICK MY MOM TAUGHT
ME, JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW.
I LIKE IT.
GOT TO GIVE KUDOS
TO MOM.
FRESH BASIL.
PARSLEY.
NOW WE GO DOWN WITH
SOME OF THE PARSLEY
THAT WAS FROZEN
THAT YOU CHOPPED.
AND DRIED PARSLEY, BASIL
AND OREGANO.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
TO HYDRATE THE SPICES.
WE'RE READY
FOR THE TOMATO SAUCE.
MY SECRET INGREDIENT.
HANG ON. HANG ON.
NO, NO, NO, NO!
WHAT IS IT?
YOU GOT LET ME AT LEAST KNOW.
NO. NO. NO.
WOW. I LIKE IT.
HOW LONG YOU LET THAT
GO FOR?
THREE HOURS.
OKAY.
SO HOW'S THAT LOOKING?
IT'S LOOKING GOOD.
REDUCIN' A LITTLE BIT,
YOU SEE THAT COLOR DARKEN UP.
I DIDN'T GET ENOUGH
ON THE FIRST TRY.
MMM.
OH, THAT IS FANTASTIC.
ON ALL KINDS OF THINGS,
FROM EGGPLANT PARMESAN...
IF YOU THINK
YOU DON'T LIKE EGGPLANT--
MMM--
THAT WOULD CONVERT PEOPLE.
TO HOMEMADE LASAGNA
AND A MASSIVE
MEATBALL SANDWICH...
IT KIND OF TASTES LIKE SPAGHETTI
ON A ROLL.
MADE FROM GROUND BEEF
AND PORK SAUSAGE.
I USE A MIXTURE
OF HOT AND MILD SAUSAGE.
ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
YES.
SO NOT TOO SPICY,
BUT GOT ENOUGH KICK. GOT IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME EGGS AND SOME GARLIC.
AND I ADD SALT, PEPPER,
PARSLEY, BREADCRUMBS.
NOW SEE, THIS IS WHERE WE TAKE
A DIFFERENCE IN OUR MEATBALLS.
I'LL TAKE MY BREAD IN BIG PIECES
AND SOAK IT IN MILK.
OH, YEAH.
I KNOW A LOT OF PEOPLE DO THAT.
YOU KNOW THAT KIND?
YEAH.
I KNOW THOSE KIND OF PEOPLE.
YEAH, I KNOW THOSE KIND.
THOSE KIND OF PEOPLE.
AND THEN ONE
OF MY LITTLE SECRETS.
I USE OATMEAL
AS A FILLER.
WHICH IS NICE,
'CAUSE WHAT GREAT TEXTURE.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
EXTRA-LEAN GROUND BEEF.
ALL RIGHT.
SO NOW...
NOW WE MIX.
HOW AM I DOING?
I MEAN, I'M HEARING...
YOU'RE DOING ALL RIGHT.
"WHY CAN'T MOOCHIE
MAKE THE MEATBALLS?"
YOU'RE DOING OKAY.
WE'LL HIRE YOU ON.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
THIS IS WHY ONE ARM
IS BIGGER
THAN THE OTHER HERE.
THIS ONE IS HUGE,
'CAUSE YOU MIX THAT WAY.
THE ORIGINAL MEASUREMENT
FOR MY MEATBALLS...
(normal voice) WAS YOUR HAND.
RIGHT THERE.
NOW HOW MANY WILL
THAT MAKE?
THIS WILL BE 28.
ARE THEY READY?
THEY'RE READY.
LET'S GET THOSE MEATBALLS
OUT OF THE OVEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIES.
LET THESE COOL.
NOW LET ME ASK YOU
A QUESTION...
WHAT'S THAT?
AS YOU'RE CUTTING THESE
BEAUTIFUL MEATBALLS IN HALF--
WHY NOT JUST MAKE
SMALLER MEATBALLS?
OH, NO, YOU CAN'T
DO THAT.
BECAUSE?
'CAUSE THAT'S HOW
EVERYBODY ELSE DOES IT.
SO THESE LITTLE BAD BOYS
ARE JUST GONNA HANG OUT.
I MEAN, WHAT A CULINARY COMPOUND
TO HANG OUT IN...
MM-HMM.
MARINARA SAUCE ALL DAY.
NOW THESE GO BACK ON THE STOVE
AND LET 'EM JUST SIT THERE
AND SIMMER A LITTLE BIT
AND STAY WARM?
MM-HMM.
GET SOME NICE HOT BREAD.
WITH CHEESE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
SO THERE'S ANOTHER REASON
WHY YOU CUT 'EM IN HALF.
LAYS DOWN FLAT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HUNGRY?
(scoffs)
SEE?
YOU SEE THE POSITIONING?
ARMS OUT.
KEEP OFF YOUR PREDATORS.
MMM.
MMM. YEAH.
THAT WAS SO WORTH
THE BURN.
THAT'S A MONEY MEATBALL.
SUBTLE DELICIOUS
THAT'LL KNOCK YOUR HEAD OFF.
MMM.
YOU GOT TO TRY THAT.
I'M A BIG MEATBALL FAN.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
NICE SPICY MEATBALL IN IT
AND LOTS OF CHEESE.
THE MARINARA ON THIS
IS JUST REALLY GOOD.
IT'S JUST A GOOD SANDWICH.
I'M TELLING YA,
BEEN TO PHILLY,
AND THIS IS
SOME PRETTY GOOD PHILLY FOOD.
FOOT-LONG PIZZA STEAK.
THANK YOU.
JUST ASK THE FOLKS
WHO GREW UP THERE.
WE COME HERE
BECAUSE IT'S REAL, AUTHENTIC
PHILADELPHIA CHEESESTEAKS.
SORT OF REMINDS ME OF WALKING
DOWN TO THE CORNER SHOP
AND GETTING A SANDWICH THERE.
IS THAT TO GO?
AND THEY'RE LIKE, "OH, FINALLY,
I FOUND A REAL CHEESESTEAK."
MMM.
DO I HAVE ANY ON HERE?
NO?
DO YOU HAVE A SMALL SHOWER
OR A TUB?
YEAH, WE DO, ACTUALLY.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO SAN DIEGO...
BEST BURGERS IN TOWN.
WHERE THEY'RE MAKING BURGERS
OUT OF JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
THEY HAVE OSTRICH.
I GET TO HAVE ALLIGATOR BURGER,
AND YOU DON'T.
WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT A BURGER JOINT,
WELL, YOU'RE PROBABLY THINKING
THE ALL-AMERICAN BURGER
WITH THE SHAKE AND THE FRIES
AND THE WHOLE GIDDYAP
UNLESS YOU'RE HERE IN SAN DIEGO,
WHERE TWO DUDES FROM GERMANY
WHO GOT OUT OF FINE DINING--
WELL, THESE CATS WILL MAKE
A BURGER OUT OF
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT
TIOLI'S CRAZEE BURGER.
KANGAROO BURGER.
KANGAROO RARE.
GATOR.
AND GATOR BURGER.
MMM. IT'S FANTASTIC.
THEY HAVE OSTRICH.
ALL KINDS OF CRAZY.
INCLUDING THE SAUCES.
CHUTNEY, FRUIT.
THE WINE-INFUSED PEARS.
ORANGE GLAZE.
(man) A VERY SWEET SAUCE.
MMM. THIS IS FABULOUS.
WHERE DID THAT COME FROM?
FROM CHEF LOTHAR MANZ...
SAUERKRAUT AND POTATO SALAD,
YEAH.
AND HIS BUDDY
WOLFGANG PETER SCHLICHT...
LET ME RING YOU UP.
TWO RESTAURANT GUYS
FROM GERMANY
WHO WANTED TO PUT A TWIST...
VENISON BURGER.
ON AN AMERICAN CLASSIC.
WE JUST WANTED TO BE DIFFERENT.
HERE WE GO.
SO THEY TOOK OVER AN ITALIAN
PLACE NAMED TIOLI'S...
CIAO BELLA.
YOU SAID IF WE KEEP
THE NAME "TIOLI'S,"
BUT WE'RE JUST GONNA THROW
"CRAZEE BURGER" ON THE END, AH.
WE STARTED WITH
1,000 BURGERS A MONTH,
AND NOW WE'RE DOING 7,000.
7,000 A MONTH.
I'VE GOT THE GATOR BURGER.
I GET TO EAT ALLIGATOR BURGER,
AND YOU DON'T.
WHAT PART OF
THE ALLIGATOR IS THIS?
THIS IS THE SIRLOIN.
FIRST WE CUT IT
A LITTLE BIT SMALLER.
ANYTHING ELSE
GOING IN THERE?
NEIN, NOTHING.
NADA.
HMM, GROUND-UP GATOR.
DO YOU EVER SERVE TATER
WITH GATOR?
NO.
JAMES SPADER
LIKES GATOR.
OKAY, SO YOU GIVE IT
A LITTLE PAT.
SO YOU COULD JUST KEEP MAKING
THEM LIKE THAT, BUT THAT--
THAT'S A BIG ONE.
NOW THIS IS ALMOST 7 OUNCES.
YOU'RE GONNA EAT HIS.
ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN, THAT'S, LIKE,
THE SURFACE OF THE SUN, BROTHER.
WHOA!
WE PUT THE BURGER ON.
THIS SIDE IS NOT SO HOT.
YEAH, OH, YEAH, WHERE
IT'S WHITE, NOT SO HOT THERE.
NOW THE HOMEMADE SEASON--
THIS IS SALT, PEPPER,
PAPRIKA AND GARLIC POWDER.
AND THAT'S IT--
JUST A LITTLE TICKLE.
FOR THE GRAVY, WE NEED
A LITTLE BIT WATER FIRST.
I DON'T KNOW THAT
I'VE SEEN MANY GRAVIES
START OUT
WITH JUST WATER IN THE PAN.
DRIED BANANAS.
AND EVEN MORE DRIED FRUIT--
APPLES, APRICOTS AND PLUMS.
CREAM AND CURRY.
ALL RIGHT, THIS IS ODD--
DRIED FRUIT, SOME CURRY
AND A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM.
THAT'S YOUR IDEA?
YES, MY IDEA.
RIGHT UP THERE
WITH THE CRAZY PART.
BURGER BUNS,
JUST A LITTLE BIT CRISPY.
IS IT READY?
YES, WE GOT IT.
AND THEN OUR RECONSTITUTED
CURRY FRUIT DRY...
♪♪
THAT'S GREAT.
I GOT TO TELL YA, I NEVER
THOUGHT I WOULD REALLY LIKE IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THAT'S AWESOME.
GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
AND THE CURRY FRUIT THING--
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT'S CRAZY!
ACTUALLY TASTES
LIKE A PORK CUTLET.
(man) SEEMS LIKE ALL THE FLAVORS
MELD TOGETHER TO MAKE
ONE VERY FINE BURGER.
THEY HAVE ALL KINDS OF BURGERS.
IT'S PRETTY FAR OUT THERE.
THIS IS THE KANGAROO BURGER.
(Lothar) WE HAVE THE MEAT
FROM AUSTRALIA.
THIS ONE'S REALLY LEAN,
90-10.
IT'S A MARSUPIAL.
YEP.
BIG WORD FOR ME.
SO NOT A LOT OF PRESSURE ON IT
SO IT DOESN'T BECOME TOUGH.
OH, NO. NO. NO.
SO THIS IS READY
TO GO?
THIS IS FINISHED.
SAME THING--PUT IT ON
THAT NUCLEAR-HOT GRILL?
LET'S PUT IT ON THE GRILL.
YES.
MAGIC SEASONINGS--SALT, PEPPER,
THE PAPRIKA AND THE GARLIC.
THIS WE SERVE
WITH HORSERADISH CREAM.
MAYONNAISE,
I HAVE SOUR CREAM.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT
OF HORSERADISH.
ALL RIGHT, I LIKE
THE WAY THIS IS GOING.
SOME SALT,
WHITE PEPPER...
ALL RIGHT.
NOT THE BLACK ONE--
AND THE LEMON JUICE.
THERE WE GO.
AND SO THE WHITE PEPPER,
SO IT DOESN'T--
THE BLACK PEPPER
DOESN'T STAND OUT.
YES.
MAKE MY...
(whistles) I'D LIKE TO SEE
THIS ON A BAKED POTATO.
KEEP ON THIS HERE.
ONE OF THE THINGS I TALK ABOUT
WHEN YOU'RE COOKING BURGERS,
USE A REALLY
HIGH TEMPERATURE.
YOU WANT TO LET IT GO FARTHER,
PUT IT TO THE COOL AREA,
BUT SEAR BOTH SIDES,
REALLY PUT A NICE CRUST ON.
YOUR BURGER.
THAT'S IT, HUH?
HAVE FUN.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I--
TRY IT.
TRY IT?
YOU TRY IT, TOO.
OKAY.
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D"
SOMEONE'S ENJOYING THE BURGER
A LITTLE BIT MORE
THAN THE HOST.
PRINCESS BITE,
CRAZY BITE.
GREAT FLAVOR,
NOT OVERCOOKED,
HORSERADISH CREAM SAUCE
IS DYNAMITE ON THERE.
I LIKE THAT.
AND SO DID YOU.
YEAH. OF COURSE,
I LIKE WHAT I COOK.
OH, SORRY.
THIS IS GETTING
OUT OF CONTROL.
IT'S VERY LEAN. IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S VERY UNIQUE. IF I DIDN'T
KNOW IT WAS SOMETHING DIFFERENT,
I WOULD THINK IT'S HAMBURGER.
THEY HAVE THE BEST BURGERS
IN TOWN.
THE BURGER--IT'S
AN ALL-AMERICAN THING.
LOOK AT THIS.
AND, REMEMBER...
THERE WE GO.
SERVED UP BY A COUPLE
OF DUDES FROM GERMANY..
I NEED THE BRIE.
IN AN OLD ITALIAN RESTAURANT.
IT'S A CRAZY VARIETY.
YOU THINK?
OSTRICH WITH LEMON CHIVE
CREAM SAUCE...
IT'S GOT A GOOD BALANCE TO IT,
A LITTLE TANGINESS TO IT,
JUST MELLOWS IT OUT.
AND CHECK OUT THE VENISON.
IT'S MILDLY GAMEY, BUT I THINK
IT'S OFFSET BY THE SWEET CREAM
AND THE WINE-INFUSED PEARS
THEY PUT IN IT.
IT'S REALLY QUITE GOOD.
FROM SANTORINI.
SANTORINI?
HALF LAMB, HALF BEEF.
IT'S EXOTIC.
GREEK. GET 1/2 POUND LAMB,
1/2 POUND BEEF.
OH, HOW BIG OF A BURGER
IS THIS?
2 1/2-POUND BURGERS.
YOU GIVE TWO OUT, SO YOU HAVE
TO ORDER IT WITH A FRIEND?
I LIKE ONE, TOO, MAYBE.
OH, OH.
WE'RE GONNA SHARE THIS ONE.
THIS WE SHARE.
OH, I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL.
SO YOU'RE
A LAMB LOVER, HUH?
OH, YEAH. ALL THINGS WITH LAMB,
I LOVE IT.
SALT, PEPPER.
WHAT'S GONNA GO ON THIS?
ON THIS WE MAKE
A TZATZIKI SAUCE.
IT'S A GREEK TRADITION.
SOUR CREAM AND YOGURT.
WE HAVE CUCUMBER,
FRESH GARLIC, FRESH MINT,
A LITTLE BIT SALT,
WHITE PEPPER
AND THE LEMON JUICE.
AND YOU GET THAT SIT
FOR A LITTLE BIT
TO LET THE FLAVORS MARRY.
THAT'S YUMMY.
YOU JUST LOVE
TO FLIP THE BURGER.
YES.
I'M THE OVER-FLIPPER.
YOU'RE THE OVER-FLIPPER.
YES.
THAT'S WHAT THEY CALL IT.
LOOK HOW JUICY THAT IS.
MMM. THAT'S AWESOME.
THE TZATZIKI AND THE LAMB
AND THE BEEF--
MAN, THAT'S IT.
AND THE SAUCE--IT'S AMAZING.
THE LAMB AND SAUCE ALTOGETHER
MAKES A REALLY GREAT BURGER.
THIS IS NOT LIKE
YOUR REGULAR BURGER JOINT.
IF YOU LOOK FOR
A BLACK-AND-WHITE CAR
IN THE PARKING LOT, YOU KNOW
YOU GOT A GOOD PLACE TO EAT.
EVERYBODY
LOVES A GOOD BURGER.
GOOD EATS, BROTHER.
THANK YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GIVE ME THE POSE.
I GOT TWO CEMITAS MILANESAS.
NEXT UP...
IT'S EXCELLENT. IT'S SO GOOD.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO THE MIDWEST
FOR A HARD-TO-FIND
MEXICAN SPECIALTY...
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF THIS.
AT A FAMILY JOINT...
CEMITA.
IN CHICAGO.
VERY DELICIOUS.
SO CHECK IT OUT.
HERE I AM IN CHICAGO,
AND I KNOW YOU'RE EXPECTING
I'M GONNA BE EATING ONE OF THOSE
KILLER CHICAGO DOGS, RIGHT?
OR MAYBE SOME PIZZA
OR ITALIAN BEEF?
BUT, NOPE, TODAY
IT'S ALL ABOUT CEMITAS
AT A PLACE CALLED
CEMITAS PUEBLA.
JUST WHEN YOU THINK YOU KNOW
YOUR MEXICAN FOOD,
TRIPLE "D" ROLLS INTO TOWN
AND FINDS THIS JOINT.
JUST A VERY TASTY SANDWICH.
C-E-M-I-T-A.
CEMITA.
I'M HAVING A CEMITA.
IT'S A KIND OF SANDWICH WITH
AVOCADO, CHIPOTLE PEPPER,
MEXICAN CHEESE
AND A KIND OF BITTER HERB.
PAPALO, MM-HMM.
PAPALO.
THE CEMITA IS ALWAYS STANDARD.
THE ONLY THING
THAT VARIES IS THE MEAT.
FROM CARNE ASADA...
VERY DELICIOUS.
AND AL PASTOR TO A SPICED PORK
CALLED CARNE ENCHILADA.
THIS IS UNIQUE.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF THIS.
'CAUSE YOU CAN'T
FIND IT ANYWHERE
OUTSIDE OF PUEBLA, MEXICO.
THE CITY IN CENTRAL MEXICO...
CEMITAS.
WHERE TONY ANTELIZ'S
MOM AND DAD ANTONIO GREW UP.
80% OF THE MENU
IS FROM PUEBLA.
NOBODY CAN SAY,
ONLY US.
MY FAMILY'S FROM PUEBLA.
NO.
WHEN I HEARD ABOUT THIS PLACE,
I WAS A LITTLE EXCITED.
'CAUSE THEY'RE DOING
ALL KINDS OF CEMITAS.
WHAT'RE YOU HAVING HERE?
AL PASTOR?
AL PASTOR.
CEMITA DE MILANESA.
THE MILANESA
IS THE POPULAR ONE.
I GOT TWO CEMITAS MILANESAS.
THIS ONE'S MADE
WITH BREADED PORK.
I GOT TO SHOW YOU
HOW I BREAD IT.
LITTLE BIT OF CHOPPED ONIONS,
LITTLE BIT OF CLOVES,
NOT A LOT, JUST A LITTLE,
BLACK PEPPER--
WE'RE BIG FANS
OF BLACK PEPPER IN MY HOUSE,
SO I PUT A LOT OF THAT IN
THERE--SOME GROUND OREGANO,
LITTLE BIT OF WHITE PEPPER,
THREE WHOLE
GARLIC CLOVES PEELED.
SO A LITTLE AJO.
AND I'M ALSO PUTTING
IN SOME GROUND AJO.
I FOLLOW MAMA'S RULES,
OR ELSE I GET IN TROUBLE.
THEN I GRAB A LITTLE BIT
OF BREADCRUMBS, ABOUT YEA MUCH.
YEA MUCH.
SHOULD WRITE THIS DOWN.
THEN WE GET OUR MILK.
ABOUT HALFWAY,
IT'S NOT REALLY HALFWAY.
DEPENDS ON WHERE
YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT.
RIGHT, IT'S ALL PERSPECTIVE.
IT'S ALL PERSPECTIVE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
I MAJORED IN HISTORY.
THEY DIDN'T TEACH ME
CULINARY COOKING STUFF.
YEAH, WHAT DO THOSE
DATES MEAN, ANYWAY?
YEAH, EXACTLY.
THIS LOOKS LIKE IT COMES
FROM THE PORK LOIN.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
GONNA LET IT SOAK.
YOU BREAD 'EM
AND THEN FRY 'EM?
I WOULD PREFER TO LET IT SIT
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
IF I FRY 'EM RIGHT AWAY, A LOT
OF THE BREAD WILL COME OUT.
SORRY.
NOW IT GOES TO THE FLATTOP?
JUST FOR A SECOND
WHILE I GET MY BREAD READY.
THAT'S A FAMILY RECIPE.
I HAVE A GENTLEMAN
WHO OWNS A BAKERY,
MAKES THAT
EXCLUSIVELY FOR ME.
SO I GRAB A LOT OF AVOCADO.
THAT BECOMES
A NATURAL MAYONNAISE.
YEAH.
SOME CHIPOTLE GOES ON THERE.
THE ADOBO--THEY BECOME LIKE
THIS MOLASSES-TYPE SYRUP.
IT JUST MASHES RIGHT IN.
OUR PORK LOIN.
THIS CHEESE--
IT'S CALLED QUESO OAXACA.
THAT'S QUESO A-LOTTA.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU CALL IT QUESO OAXACA.
PAPALO--MY MOM GROWS THIS
FOR ME IN THE SUMMER.
IT'S VERY PUNGENT,
BUT IT GIVES THE CEMITA
A WHOLE WORLD OF TASTE.
WOW.
THAT MAKES ARUGULA
TASTE LIKE ICEBERG.
(whistles)
PUT SOME OLIVE
ON THE TOP.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
MMM. DUDE, THIS IS GREAT.
WOW.
THAT IS DIFFERENT.
IT'S SUCH A UNIQUE FLAVOR.
COOKED PERFECTLY.
WELL, THAT
JUST MESSED IT UP.
I HAVE TO COME TO CHICAGO NOW
TO GET MEXICAN FOOD.
NOT JUST ANY MEXICAN FOOD
(speaking Spanish)
REMEMBER,
THIS STUFF'S FROM PUEBLA,
WHERE TONY'S PARENTS WERE BORN.
WE WANTED TO MAKE IT
AS AUTHENTIC AS POSSIBLE.
WHEN WE STARTED BUYING
INGREDIENTS HERE,
IT JUST WOULDN'T COME OUT
WITH THE SAME FLAVOR.
SO WHAT WE HAVE TO DO, MAN,
IS WE GOT TO GO TO MEXICO.
THAT'S RIGHT, EVERY MONTH
OR SIX WEEKS, DAD'S GOING HOME.
WE GET OUR CINNAMON,
OUR OREGANO.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
WE GET
IS OUR CHIPOTLES
AND OUR QUESO OAXACA.
THE CHEESE IS REALLY FRESH.
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
PRETTY LEGIT.
AND SO IS GRANDMA'S RECIPE FOR
THE CHIPOTLES IN ADOBO SAUCE.
THIS RIGHT HERE
IS WHAT GIVES MY CEMITA
MOST OF ITS FLAVOR.
THIS IS WHAT'S CALLED
A MORITA CHIPOTLE.
I THINK MORITA
USUALLY MEANS SMALL.
I USE RAW SUGARCANE.
HOLY MOLEY.
REAL SWEET,
IT'S JUST LIKE NATURAL SUGAR.
DUMP THAT IN THERE.
DRIED THYME.
I LOVE OREGANO,
SO I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE BIT
MORE THAN I'VE BEEN TOLD TO.
KIND OF YOUR RESTAURANT,
TOO, SO...
YEAH, I KNOW.
SOME BAY LEAVES, DRY.
SOME DRY CLOVES.
FIVE OR SIX GARLIC HEADS.
YOU DON'T GOT TO PEEL 'EM.
TWO, THREE THINGIES
OF SALT.
TWO OR THREE THINGIES
OF SALT?
THINGIES, YEAH.
GIANT CINNAMON STICKS.
LOOK AT THESE.
THEY'RE NOT THE ONES YOU FIND
IN YOUR NORMAL MARKET...
NO.
WHERE THEY'RE THIS BIG.
WE GET THAT FROM MEXICO.
A WHOLE LOT OF ONIONS.
AND A WHOLE LOT OF ONIONS,
HERE COOKING WITH TONY.
ABOUT A GALLON AND A 1/2
OF PLAIN OLD WHITE VINEGAR.
THIS IS--I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA,
I THINK I'VE SEEN IT ALL MADE,
BUT THIS TOPS IT.
OKAY, I'M DYING
TO KNOW WHAT THIS IS.
LOOKS LIKE SOMEONE
DIDN'T CLEAN THE FISH TANK.
EXACTLY, RIGHT.
IT'S A PINEAPPLE BRINE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT'S REALLY
CALLED. THAT'S WHAT I CALL IT.
I SLICE UP SOME PINEAPPLES
AND ADD SOME VINEGAR, SOME WATER
AND SOME OF THE RAW
SUGARCANE.
BUT YOU ONLY PUT
THE LIQUID IN.
I CAN KEEP THAT, 'CAUSE THAT CAN
LAST ME FOR A COUPLE MONTHS.
OH, REALLY, YOU CAN KEEP
USING THAT PINEAPPLE.
KEEP USING THAT PINEAPPLE.
GRANDMA SAYS
THAT IT'S GOOD,
AND THAT'S WHAT SHE DOES BACK
HOME, AND THAT'S WHAT WE DO.
DON'T ARGUE WITH GRANDMA.
NO. NO, NO, NO.
AND THEN FINALLY WE JUST TOP OFF
THE POT WITH JUST WATER
AND LET IT BOIL FOR
ABOUT SEVEN EIGHT HOURS.
ARE WE GONNA STRAIN IT?
NO, LET IT SIT IN
ITS OWN JUICES.
SO HAVE CHIPOTLES
COOKING ALL THE TIME.
MMM.
A CLASSIC FLAVOR
ON EVERY CLASSIC CEMITA
FROM CARNE ASADA...
IT'S EXCELLENT. IT'S SO GOOD.
TO TONY'S SPICY AL PASTOR...
WOW. IT'S DELICIOUS.
OR WHATEVER YOU WANT.
I HAD A CUSTOMER.
SHE COMES IN HERE EVERY WEEK.
AND SHE WOULD ASK FOR A CEMITA
WITH MILANESA, CARNE ENCHILADA
AND HAM.
BRING IT.
ALL RIGHT, GUY.
MMM.
THAT'S A WHOLE BUNCH OF FLAVOR,
I'LL TELL YOU THAT MUCH.
OH, MAN, THAT'S GREAT.
I WOULD LOVE THIS.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU GOT EVERY TEXTURE OF PORK
YOU CAN GET IN THERE.
I'VE HAD IT SINCE
I WAS A KID.
THEY USED TO SELL
THESE ON THE STREET.
WHAT I MAKE MORE OF
IS ON-THE-GO FOOD.
WHEN YOU GO TO THE MARKET,
WHEN YOU GO DOWN THE STREET.
THANKS A LOT.
SO WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN?
AND THE CEMITAS
ARE JUST THE START.
THIS IS A TACO ARABE.
TACO ARABE.
A PUEBLA SPECIALTY BORN
IN THE MIDDLE EAST...
MEXICAN COUSIN
OF THE SHAWARMA.
THERE YOU GO. YES.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
GOOD?
MAYBE WE SHOULD MAKE SIX MORE,
AND I'LL TELL YA.
I GOT TWO CEMITAS MILANESAS.
AT CEMITAS PUEBLA
IN CHICAGO....
THAT IS TO GO?
THEY'RE MAKING A SANDWICH
CALLED A CEMITA.
CARNE ASADA CEMITA,
VERY DELICIOUS.
FROM PUEBLA, MEXICO,
WERE TONY ANTELIZ'S PARENTS
GREW UP. ..
FOR YOU?
AND WHERE THEY'RE CRANKING OUT
ALL KINDS OF SPECIALTIES.
WHERE MY POPS IS FROM,
THEY MAKE THIS TACO,
AND IT'S REGIONAL
TO WHERE HE'S FROM.
IT'S CALLED TACO ARABE.
THE WHO-THE-WHO-THE?
ARAB IN SPANISH.
A-R-A-B-E.
EXACTLY.
IT'S UNIQUE.
THESE THINGS ARE SO GOOD.
I LIKE TO CALL TACO ARABE
THE COUSIN OF THE SHAWARMA.
MEXICAN COUSIN
OF THE SHAWARMA.
THE CLASSIC MIDDLE EASTERN
MEAT ON A SPIT.
FOR WHATEVER REASON, THEY HAD
A LEBANESE INFLUENCE THERE.
LOT OF MERCHANTS WENT OVER,
OPENED UP THEIR BUSINESS,
AND I GUESS THE TWO CULTURES
JUST FUSED
AND MADE WHAT'S CALLED
A TACO ARABE.
WE'RE GONNA GET A COUPLE
SERRANO PEPPERS, DRY OREGANO.
WOW, LOOK HOW RUSTIC
THAT LOOKS.
WE GET THAT FROM MEXICO--
LITTLE BIT OF CLOVES,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
SOME WHITE PEPPER, PARSLEY.
EVERYBODY, STEMS AND ALL?
YEAH.
THE MORE THE BETTER.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
WHITE VINEGAR.
IN CASE YOU JUST TUNED IN,
THAT'S NOT A MARGARITA.
WE'RE GONNA GRAB
OUR PORK SHOULDER.
WE'LL LET THIS MARINATE
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
TWO, THREE HOURS.
IS THIS GOING ON A ROTISSERIE?
IS THAT WHERE
THE ARABE PART COMES IN?
YEAH.
ONCE WE GET 'EM ALL MARINATED,
THEY WE COME OVER,
AND WE STACK 'EM UP LIKE--
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A BEAUTIFUL
BALL OF MEAT, MY FRIEND.
PARTYIN' IN CHICAGO
WITH A BALL OF MEAT.
THE ONIONS, PORK SHOULDER,
ONIONS, PORK SHOULDER, ONIONS.
WHY CAN'T IT BE PORK SHOULDER,
ONION, PORK SHOULDER, ONION,
PORK SHOULDER?
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT IT TO.
IT'S ALWAYS YOUR WAY.
I LOVE SHAWARMA...
SIMILAR.
IN REAL GYRO.
OH, HAPPY.
TUCK THAT IN THERE.
I AM JUST OUT OF
MY MIND RIGHT NOW.
THINK I COULD FIT THAT
IN THE CAR?
THEY JUST SLICE IT UP AND DOWN
TO START WITH
AND JUST LET THE JUICES FLOW
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
YOU KNOW WHAT THOSE ARE. THOSE
ARE TEARS FROM THE FLAVOR ANGEL.
PUT THAT ON THE FLATTOP
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
GET CHARRED ON THE OUTSIDE.
YOU DON'T USE
A REGULAR EVERYDAY TORTILLA.
WHAT YOU USE
IS A REAL THIN PITA.
WHAT WAS THAT
RIGHT OVER THERE?
THAT'S JUST MEAT THAT FELL.
THE ONLY THING A TACO ARABE
TAKES IS THE CHIPOTLE SAUCE
THAT WE PURéE
FROM THE CHIPOTLES.
MMM.
OH, YOU'RE NOT READING
MY MIND? OH.
MEAT'S SUPER TENDER.
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR BY ITSELF.
HERE'S THE FUNNY THING
IS THAT CHIPOTLE HAS A LITTLE
BIT OF SWEETNESS TO IT,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
BUT IT COMPLEMENTS
IT PERFECTLY.
THIS IS BANANAS.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
PLáTANOS.
THIS, BAR NONE,
WITH THE SAUCE,
WITH THIS RIGHT HERE,
THE SECRET SAUCE,
MAKES IT ALL WORTHWHILE.
THIS ENTIRE PLACE
IS VERY AUTHENTIC.
AL PASTOR.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
CAN'T GET THIS ANYWHERE ELSE.
EVERY TIME I COME TO CHICAGO,
I MAKE A POINT TO COME HERE.
A GO-TO SPOT.
ENJOY, MY FRIENDS.
YOUR GRANDMA AND YOUR PARENTS
HAVE TAUGHT YOU RIGHT, MAN.
THANK YOU.
SO WAS THAT A MONEY ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU KNOW WHAT I FEEL LIKE?
MAYBE YOU COULD PUT
A LITTLE HAT ON ME
AND THROW A PEANUT
ONCE IN A WHILE.
(chattering like a monkey)
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
(mumbles)