HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
I NEED TWO UP ON ONE.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
BEST HOT DOG IN TOWN.
HUGE CHUNK OF MEAT.
MMM.
BURGERS AND DOGS...
BY THE ARMFUL.
I HAVEN'T EVEN TAKEN IT TO
THE COLLARBONE OR EARLOBE YET.
AND A BALTIMORE LEGEND.
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT A G&A HOT DOG
THAT JUST MAKES ME
FEEL AT HOME.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN
MAKING CONEYS...
THE CONEY SAUCE, ISN'T IT?
THAT'S WHAT DOES IT.
FOR MORE THAN 80 YEARS.
WE KEPT ALL THE OLD RECIPES.
WE KEPT EVERYTHING THE SAME.
AND THE BURGER'S
TOTALLY THEIR WAY.
CONEY ISLAND BURGER--
THAT'S A HIT.
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS...
WOULD YOU LIKE A GLASS?
THE BAR WITH BURGERS
THAT'LL LIGHT YA UP.
THAT IS HOT!
I PERSONALLY
LIKE THE BURN. WHEW!
AND YOU CAN GET YOUR DOGS
TWO AT A TIME.
DOUBLE DOG!
BACON, CHEESE,
TWO HOT DOGS
SHOVED INSIDE OF A BUN.
IT'S SO GOOD.
WIENERY.
AND THE MINNEAPOLIS DIVE...
AMAZING.
IT'S FAST.
IT'S INEXPENSIVE.
GREAT DOG.
WHERE DOGS AND BURGERS...
WHOO-HOO!
WE HAVE YOUR BUN COOKING.
WE GOT THE DOGS HOT.
ARE A ONE-MAN SHOW.
I'M WORKING,
GETTING THE FOOD,
MAKING THE COFFEE,
TAKING THE MONEY,
DOING THE DISHES.
ALL AT THE SAME TIME?
I CAN'T WAIT
TO SEE HOW THIS GOES.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
IN 1927, A GREEK IMMIGRANT BY
THE NAME OF GREGORY DIACUMACOS
OPENED A HOT DOG STAND
IN BALTIMORE,
SERVING CONEY ISLAND-STYLE DOGS
WITH HIS OWN CHILI SAUCE RECIPE.
NOW IT WAS A HIT.
I MEAN, A BIG HIT.
AND 81 YEARS LATER,
IT STILL IS.
(woman) I NEED TWO UP ON ONE.
FIVE UP ON THREE.
TWO HOLD THE ONION.
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT A G&A HOT DOG...
ENJOY, ENJOY.
MAKES ME FEEL AT HOME.
IS THAT YUMMY?
(woman) IT TASTES
JUST SCRUMPTIOUS.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAVEN.
THIS IS LIKE
AN INSTITUTION.
MY GRANDFATHER'S
BEEN COMING HERE
SINCE HE WAS A KID,
MY FATHER--
NO.
TAKE THESE.
AND IT ALL BEGAN
WITH OWNER ANDY FARANTOS'S
GREAT UNCLE GREGORY
WHO PARTNERED UP
WITH HIS COUSIN ALEX
AND STARTED A TRADITION.
HE HAD IT
FROM 1927 TO 1966,
AND MY FATHER TOOK IT OVER
IN '66 TO '88 WITH MY UNCLE.
AND THEN IT WAS ANDY'S TURN.
PICK IT UP.
WE KEPT ALL THE OLD RECIPES.
WE KEPT EVERYTHING THE SAME.
AND KEPT
THE CROWDS PACKING IN.
BEST HOT DOG IN TOWN.
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE KID,
WE USED TO COME UP HERE
AND GET HOT DOGS, AND WATCH HIM
TURN THEM IN THE WINDOW.
(Andy) YOU'RE GONNA ENJOY
THIS ONE.
LOADED WITH
THE ORIGINAL CONEY SAUCE...
MMM. DELICIOUS.
ANDY HAS STILL NOT TOLD ME
WHAT THE SECRET INGREDIENTS ARE.
ON THE DOGS AND THE BURGERS,
EVEN AN OMELET.
IT'S THE CONEY SAUCE,
ISN'T IT?
YES.
THAT'S WHAT DOES IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
NOW IT'S TIME TO MAKE
THE CONEY ISLAND SAUCE.
YES.
EVERY DAY, WE GET FRESH
GROUND BEEF DELIVERED.
DO A LOT OF GROUND BEEF
AROUND HERE.
YEAH, WE SURE DO.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA GET
IN THERE?
YEAH, YOU GOT TO GET IN.
YOU GOT TO BREAK DOWN
THE GROUND BEEF.
HOW MANY DAYS A WEEK
DO YOU WORK?
SIX DAYS A WEEK.
HOW MANY HOURS A DAY?
16 HOURS A DAY.
16 HOURS A DAY,
6 DAYS A WEEK.
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT,
A LITTLE MORE WATER.
AND THEN, GUY, I NEED
THE PAPRIKA. HERE WE GO.
THE CELERY SALT,
THE CHILI POWDER.
I'M GONNA ATTACH THE MILK
CRATES TO YOUR BOOTS
AND MAKE, LIKE,
MILK CRATE SNOWSHOES.
THANK YOU, GUY.
THAT'D BE GREAT.
AND THEN YOU CAN HAVE THIS.
AND THEN YOU GO
AROUND BEING 6'6".
COMING UP ON CHRISTMAS.
GIVE THEM TO ME.
I LIKE THAT.
SO THIS IS OUR MIXTURE.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE BEEF SOUP.
WE BRING IT
TO A HARD BOIL,
AND THEN WE SIMMER IT
FOR ABOUT--
MMM. I LIKE
THE FLAVOR ALREADY.
(woman) CHILI CHEESE
AND ONION.
THE CHILI GOES ON PERFECT--
GREAT COMBINATION.
(woman) COMBINATION,
AND TWO UP ON ONE.
(man) THAT HAS EVERYTHING.
IT HAS ONIONS, KETCHUP,
MUSTARD AND THEN CHILI SAUCE,
AND THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT
TASTE THE BEST.
I'M USUALLY
ABOUT A 3-BITER.
THAT'S ONE.
MMM.
THAT'S GREAT.
NICE AND JUICY DOG.
CRAZY MEAT CONCOCTION
ON TOP.
WHITE ONION'S PERFECT.
BUN'S NICE AND STEAMED.
AND IT COSTS $1.90?
THAT'S IT.
IF I WAS A COLLEGE STUDENT,
I COULD LIVE HERE.
YOU TASTE THE HOT DOG.
YOU TASTE THE ONIONS.
YOU TASTE THE CHILI.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S THE BEST HOT DOG
I'VE EVER HAD.
AND YOU GET IT QUICK.
I NEED TWO UP ON ONE.
THEY HAVE A CODE
ALL THEIR OWN.
(woman) THREE UP ON ONE,
HOLD THE MUSTARD.
THREE HOT DOGS
FOR TWO PEOPLE,
THEY SAY THREE UP
ON TWO.
SO I'M GONNA CALL THEM
OUT TO YOU, OKAY?
SEVEN UP THREE.
SEVEN UP ON THREE.
TWO ONION, MUSTARD.
NO.
TWO HOLD CHILI.
HUH?
YOU HAVE TO HOLD
THE CHILI IF--
MAYBE I NEED
TO GET SOME TRAINING.
IF YOU WANT ONION AND MUSTARD,
THEN YOU SAY, "HOLD THE CHILI."
THAT WAY I KNOW
IT'S ONION AND MUSTARD.
SO I DON'T HAVE TO SAY
"HOLD THE CHILI?"
IF YOU WANT ONION AND MUSTARD,
YOU SAY HOLD THE CHILI.
IT'S A LOT EASIER.
OH, BECAUSE IT
HAS MUSTARD--
OH. OKAY,
FORGET IT THEN.
THEY WASTE NO TIME--
TWO UP ON ONE OR ONE UP ON TWO,
AND THEY HAVE IT
OUT TO YOU IN NO TIME FLAT.
ANDY, HE WOULD HAVE EIGHT
OR NINE HOT DOGS LINED UP
ON HIS WRIST AND ARM--
9 OF THEM DONE IN 30 SECONDS.
I WANT TEN.
I CAN'T.
THE ELBOW JOINT'S RIGHT THERE.
SEVEN.
I CAN'T DO TEN, GUY.
I CAN DO EIGHT.
YOU CAN DO 12 NOW.
UP TO MY SHOULDER BLADE.
YOU GRADUATED.
I HAVEN'T EVEN TAKEN IT TO
THE COLLARBONE OR EARLOBE YET.
AND AFTER THEIR LINED UP,
ANDY'S THROWING IN SOME FRIES--
BALTIMORE STYLE...
THE GRAVY IS WHAT MAKES
THE FRENCH FRIES.
AND EVEN THAT'S HOMEMADE.
YOU GOT GRAVY
ON YOUR FRIES?
(man) YES.
THIS IS THE FIRST PLACE I EVER
HAD FRENCH FRIES AND GRAVY.
(Guy) FRENCH FRIES
AND GRAVY?
I WAS, LIKE,
12 YEARS OLD,
AND I'VE BEEN
EATING THEM EVER SINCE.
I KNOW
IT'S A FAVORITE HERE.
MAYBE IT'S JUST
A BALTIMORE THING.
SO YOU DIP THE FRY
IN THE GRAVY?
YEAH.
CAN I TRY ONE? NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT AT ALL.
THEY'RE THE BEST FRIES.
I'D DIP THE DOG IN THAT--
MY HAND.
HE'S GOT GREAT FOOD.
NOW WHAT DO YOU NORMALLY
HAVE WHEN YOU COME IN?
I USUALLY GO
FOR THE SLIDERS.
THE SLIDERS
ARE THE LITTLE BURGERS?
LITTLE BURGERS.
WHAT ARE YOU USING?
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
REALLY? EACH ONE OF THEM
GOES ON THEIR OWN LITTLE--
YEAH.
THEY EACH GET THEIR OWN
DEDICATED PUDDLE.
IF YOU'RE GONNA USE FAT, THAT'S
THE KIND OF GOOD FAT TO USE.
SO YOU THROW
SOME CHEESE ON THERE.
HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE ONION WATER
FOR SOME STEAM AND FLAVOR,
AND NOW YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
YEAH.
MMM.
I GOT TO TELL YOU,
THE BUTTER CRUST...
IS REALLY GOOD.
IT'S JUICY.
THAT'S ABOUT AS GOOD A BURGER
AS YOU CAN GET ANYWHERE.
UNLESS YOU WANT ONE
WITH CONEY SAUCE.
NOW THAT RIGHT THERE
IS A CONEY ISLAND BURGER?
THAT'S A CONEY ISLAND BURGER.
IT'S NOT LIKE
A REGULAR HAMBURGER.
SOME ONIONS, CHILI
AND STEAMED BURGER.
IT'S LIKE MEATLOAF
WITH ONIONS.
I GOT TO HAVE
ONE OF THOSE.
SO WE'VE GOT
GROUND BEEF AND EGGS.
(ring)
I LIKE THE RING.
IT'S LIKE WE'RE CALLING
PEOPLE TO FOOD SERVICE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
PEPPER.
PRECISE MEASURING.
VERY PRECISE.
OKAY. WHOA.
WE ADD LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC.
WE GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
(muttering indistinctly)
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW.
YOU TELL TELL ME HOW TO.
JUST SAY IT FAST, 'CAUSE
NO ONE WILL EVER KNOW.
SO THE BREADCRUMBS.
YOU GONNA EYEBALL THIS?
WE EYEBALL IT, AND THEN
HAVE TO START MIXING IT.
AND IF YOU CAN HOLD THE BOWL,
I'D REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
SO I'M SPOTTING YOU?
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE--
THIS IS MY WORKOUT.
A LITTLE MORE BREADCRUMBS.
MORE BREADCRUMBS?
OKAY, NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
SCOOP IT OUT, BALL 'EM UP,
AND I THROW THEM IN HERE.
THEN HE'S BREADING THEM
WITH CRACKER MEAL.
SHAKE IT UP A LITTLE BIT
THERE AND PAT THEM DOWN.
SO THESE ARE GONNA GET
FRIED UP.
WE COOK THEM
ALL THE WAY THROUGH,
AND THEN WE PUT THEM
IN A COOL DOWN STAGE.
OVERNIGHT TO TIGHTEN THEM UP.
THEN THEY STEAM THEM
WITH ONIONS
AND TOP THEM OFF WITH PAPRIKA.
(Guy) IT'S DONE.
I CAN PULL THAT OUT,
PUT IT ON A BUN,
HIT IT WITH SOME ONIONS,
A LITTLE CONEY SAUCE--
TIME TO EAT. MMM.
IT'S KIND OF SWEET.
IT'S THE ONION.
SURE IS MOIST.
IS IT GOOD?
OH, IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S A HIT.
MMM. ALWAYS GOOD.
IT'S GREAT. THAT'S ALL
I CAN SAY. IT'S GREAT.
(man) HASN'T CHANGED.
THERE YOU GO, JOHN.
IT'S THE SAME. THE FOOD
IS STILL THE GREATEST.
THIS IS WHAT BALTIMORE'S
ALL ABOUT.
THIS PLACE IS A LANDMARK.
IT IS A LANDMARK.
IT'S A LEGEND.
MY MOM CAME HERE.
MY DAD CAME HERE.
HOW LONG HAVE
YOU BEEN COMING HERE?
SINCE I WAS HER AGE.
I'M HERE. ONE DAY
I'LL BRING MY CHILDREN UP.
WE ARE COMFORTABLE
DOING IT OLD-SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE KIND OF JOINT--
I WANT TO EAT WHERE HE COOKS.
SERRANOS COMING OUT.
UP NEXT...
HOTTER IS BETTER.
OH, MAN.
WE'RE HEADING TO TEXAS...
THE BURGER'S,
LIKE, THIS THICK.
TO TURN UP THE HEAT.
THE HOT IS HOT!
THAT'S PRETTY PERFECT.
HERE IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
THERE'S A WHOLE LOT GOING ON
ON 6th STREET,
WHERE YOU CAN HEAR MUSIC
SEVEN NIGHTS A WEEK,
YOU CAN HIT THE BARS,
AND WHEN YOU'RE HUNGRY,
YOU CAN GRAB A BURGER
AT A LITTLE DIVE
CALLED CASINO EL CAMINO.
IT'S THE BEST BURGER
IN TOWN.
(man) HUGE CHUNK OF MEAT.
ALL THE BURGERS
ARE THIS 12-OUNCE MONSTER.
Sí.
JUICY AND TENDER
AS IT CAN BE.
MMM.
(Guy) PERFECT--MEDIUM-RARE.
GRILLED RIGHT
AND TOPPED WITH EVERYTHING
FROM CHEESE
TO THICK-CUT BACON...
EVERYTHING'S BETTER
WITH BACON.
AND FRESH ROASTED CHILIES...
SERRANOS COMING OUT.
TO CRANK UP THE HEAT...
I PERSONALLY LIKE
THE BURN. WHEW.
YOU CAN'T GET IT
HOT ENOUGH.
TEXAS HOT,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE FRIES...
VERDE CHILI FRIES.
FRIED TO PERFECTION.
AND 1/4-POUND DOGS.
EVERYTHING'S BIGGER
IN TEXAS.
THE FOOD IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT'S A UNIQUE PLACE.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN
A 1975 BAD HORROR MOVIE.
THANK YOU.
YEAH.
THAT'S A COMPLIMENT.
WHEN I FIRST
OPENED UP THE PLACE,
MY FRIEND'S SAID, "WOW, THIS
IS LIKE GOING TO CASINO'S HOUSE,
EXCEPT YOU HAVE TO PAY
FOR DRINKS."
IS CASINO YOUR REAL NAME?
AS FAR AS ANYBODY
NEEDS TO KNOW, YES.
ANYTHING ELSE?
CASINO
IS THE COOLEST PLACE.
YOU OKAY?
EVEN IF HE'S NOT
FROM AROUND HERE.
WOULD YOU LIKE A GLASS?
I'M NOT CATCHING A TEXAS
ACCENT HERE. I'M CATCHING--
IT'S NEW YORK.
FROM LONG ISLAND TO BUFFALO
AND THEN DOWN HERE.
AS A MUSICIAN.
THEN HE ENDED UP
REMODELING THIS JOINT
INTO THE KIND OF HANGOUT
HE MISSED FROM BACK EAST.
WE WANTED TO HAVE
GOOD FOOD AND...
TWO BUFFALO BURGERS.
BE ABLE TO HAVE FOOD
UNTIL ALMOST CLOSE.
THANKS A LOT, MAN.
ORDER UP!
EIGHT BURGERS.
AND HE'S GOT A GUY NAMED PUPPY
MANNING THE GRILL.
WE TAKE A 12-OUNCE PATTY.
80-20?
80-20.
AND WHAT BURGER
ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
A BUFFALO BURGER.
IT'S THE PERFECT BLEND
OF HOT SAUCE AND BLUE CHEESE.
BUT THIS
IS A VERY POPULAR ONE?
THIS IS ONE OF OUR MOST
POPULAR BURGERS.
SMOTHERED IN WING SAUCE...
OH, MY GOSH--
THE WING SAUCE!
A LOT OF CAYENNE PEPPER,
A LOT OF TABASCO...
BARBECUE SAUCE.
RED WINE VINEGAR.
ON TOP OF THAT CAYENNE,
YOU COULD PUT A ROLL
OF DIMES IN THERE,
AND NO ONE WOULD KNOW.
WE MIX THAT UP INTO A NICE
LITTLE TASTY BASE.
WOW, THAT'S HOT!
YOU RUB SOME OF THAT ON YOUR
CHEST, YOU'LL BE CLEARED OUT.
I'M NOT HAVING THAT
ON ANYTHING.
THE LAST STEP WE HAVE
IS WE FILL IT WITH A--
THE NORMAL HOT SAUCE
THAT MOST PEOPLE PUT
ON THEIR BUFFALO WINGS?
WE GOT TO SHAKE IT AGAIN.
IT'S GOOD.
THERE BETTER BE
SOME PEPTO-BISMOL
AND BLUE CHEESE
COMING WITH THIS.
IF YOU CALL THE BAKERY,
THEY'LL MAKE THE BUN BIGGER.
THEN WE HAVE A BEAUTIFUL--
LOOK AT THAT NICE
MEDIUM-RARE.
MMM. OH.
THE HOT IS HOT!
I'VE HAD A LOT OF BURGERS
THAT HAVE BEEN CALLED
A BUFFALO BURGER.
THAT'S PRETTY PERFECT.
THAT TASTES ABOUT AS CLOSE
TO IT AS I HAVE EVER SEEN.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS,
I GOT A BUFFALO.
HOW'S THE BURGER?
IT'S A PERFECT
CONCOCTION. YEAH.
ENSEMBLE.
AND AS LONG
AS YOU'RE DOING HOT,
HOW ABOUT
FRESH ROASTED SERRANOS
ON SOMETHING CALLED
THE AMARILLO?
I HEAR THAT YOU'VE BEEN EATING
BURGERS AROUND HERE FOREVER.
AMARILLO BURGER AT LEAST
THREE TIMES A WEEK.
NOW WHY
THE AMARILLO BURGER?
I GO FOR
THE ROASTED SERRANOS.
(Puppy) THROW 'EM IN A OVER
THAT'S AT 500 DEGREES,
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE A FEW
AND THROW THEM
ON TOP OF THE BURGER.
AND YOU'RE COMPLETELY INSANE
IF YOU THINK I'M GONNA EAT 'EM.
JALAPEÑO PEPPER JACK CHEESE,
CILANTRO MAYO.
CILANTRO MAYO?
JUST MAYONNAISE AND TWO
BUNCHES OF CHOPPED CILANTRO.
IF THIS BURNS ME...
MMM.
THAT IS HOT!
WAS THERE MAYONNAISE
EVEN IN THERE?
THE SERRANOS, MAN,
THOSE ARE SMOKING!
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
WHERE'S THAT SAUCE?
THE WING SAUCE?
MM-HMM.
GIVE ME A LITTLE SHOT
OF THAT ON THERE.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I HAVE HEARTBURN.
SEE, YOU GOT A BIG PEPPER
RIGHT IN THERE.
YOU GET THAT GUY. YOU GOT TO
LET IT SIT FOR A LITTLE BIT.
THERE IT GOES.
FEEL LOCKED IN?
THAT'S WHEN THE MILK
COMES INTO PLAY.
YOU'RE ALL GOOD TO GO.
THE THINGS YOU LEARN
ON "TRIPLE D."
BEYOND THE AMARILLO,
THEY'VE GOT BURGERS
ALL OVER THE MAP.
MARK, L.A.!
YEAH, THAT ONE
COMES WITH SPOUTS.
PITTS!
MUSHROOMS AND MELTED PROVOLONE.
CHICAGO!
(woman) IT'S GOT BEEF
AND IT'S GOT BACON.
CHEESE MELTED PERFECTLY.
IT COMES OUT
JUST STEAMING AWESOME.
AND THE DOGS...
LIKE FROM A CART
ON THE STREET IN NEW YORK.
YOU CAN EVER GET 'EM GRILLED
AND THEN FRIED.
NOW WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOU LIKED ON YOUR DOG?
MUSTARD AND ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT OF KRAUT.
RELISH.
ALL-BEEF HOT DOG?
ALL-BEEF.
NICE AND JUICY. I LIKE
A LITTLE FRY ON IT.
AND IF ONE'S GOOD,
TWO ARE BETTER.
DOUBLE DOG TEXAS TOMMY.
BACON, CHEESE,
TWO HOT DOGS
SHOVED INSIDE OF A BUN.
IT'S SO GOOD.
NICE AND TENDER.
REAL CHEDDAR ON TOP.
THAT'S A GOOD DOG.
NOW THE FRIES,
SOMETHING A LITTLE BIT
ON THE DIFFERENT SIDE.
TOMATILLO CHILI VERDE FRIES.
JUST LIKE CHILI CHEESE FRIES,
ONLY WE USE
TOMATILLO VERDE SALSA.
SO WE'RE MAKING
A CHILI VERDE.
SO TOMATILLOS--
THESE LOOK DYNAMITE.
SO WE HAVE SOME POBLANOS
AND SOME JALAPEÑOS.
ALL RIGHT, SO THESE
BAD BOYS ARE ALL DONE.
WHOOP!
GO AHEAD
AND CUT THE STEMS OFF.
THERE'S GOT TO BE
SERRANOS GOING IN.
OH, YEAH, HALF THE AMOUNT
THAT HE PUT ON MY BURGER.
TWO BUNCHES OF CILANTRO.
LOTS AND LOTS
AND LOTS OF GARLIC.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS STARTING OUT.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
ABOUT 2 CUPS OF WATER.
YOU GO IN. YOU JUST
START MUSHING IT UP.
AND DO YOU
SEASON IT AFTERWARDS?
MMM. TASTES GREAT
LIKE IT IS.
WHILE THAT IS COOKING,
WE'RE GONNA START SOME QUESO.
PROCESSED
WHITE CHEESE. OKAY.
DICED TOMATOES
WITH GREEN CHILIES.
WE TOP IT OFF WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF MILK.
AND THEN THAT ALL GOES
ON TOP OF THE FRIES.
FRESH-CUT
DOUBLE-FRY THOSE.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY TO DO IT
IF YOU'RE GONNA FRESH-CUT THEM.
THAT NICE TENDER CENTER, THEN
THEY CRUNCH ON THE OUTSIDE.
MMM.
THAT'S MY RECIPE.
WOW. MMM.
GOOD CHEESY FLAVOR.
WHOA, THERE'S SOME HEAT.
NICE SPICE.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE THAT
SAUCE ON ANYTHING.
THIS IS BAR FOOD
DONE RIGHT, MAN.
BAR FOOD DONE RIGHT.
ABSOLUTELY.
GOT TO LOVE IT.
ALL OF IT--
THE FRIES...
OH, MAN.
THE DOGS,
THE BURGERS...
IT'S AWESOME.
BURGER'S, LIKE, THIS THICK.
THE HEAT...
HOTTER IS BETTER.
AND THE JOINT ITSELF.
EXCEPT IT'S NOT THE SAME
OLD STUFF EVERYBODY ELSE HAS.
WE WANT TO BE THE PART
AND PARCEL. THE TOTAL NUT.
THE PART AND PARCEL.
THE TOTAL NUT.
YES.
WOW. YOU OUGHT TO PUT
THAT ON A SHIRT.
UP NEXT...
HOT DOG IN A STEAMED BUN.
WE'RE GOING TO MINNESOTA...
THIS IS A HONKER. MM-HMM.
WHERE THIS GUY
IS DOING IT ALL.
ALL RIGHTY, ALL RIGHTY.
POLISH CHICAGO?
ONE DOG AT A TIME.
ONE ORDER DOWN.
IT'S WORTH THE WAIT
EVERY TIME.
I'M CLOSE TO THE CORNER
OF CEDAR AND RIVERSIDE
NEAR DOWNTOWN MINNEAPOLIS.
NOW THIS JOINT--
IT'S NOT A DINER.
IT'S NOT A DRIVE-IN.
THERE'S NO ARGUMENT.
THIS ONE'S A DIVE.
THE WIENERY--RUN BY A DUDE
THAT'S MAKING HOT DOGS
AND HAMBURGERS
HIS OWN UNIQUE WAY.
I GOT THE UPSETTER--
FRIED EGG, BACON.
ON A POLISH.
AND IT'S MONEY?
DEFINITELY.
MR. SUNSHINE.
TWO DOGS, BRO?
THE HAIRY BRAIN IS GOOD.
IT'S NAMED AFTER
THE HAIRY BRAIN.
WHOO-HOO!
CHOP, CHOP, CHOP, CHOP.
YOU CUT TO ORDER?
YES.
SO EVERY TIME
SOMEBODY ORDERS--
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
THAT MEANS EVERY BURGER...
LUKE BURGER WITH BACON.
EVERY DOG...
ORDER UP.
FRESH-CUT TOPPINGS...
ALL RIGHT, CHICAGO.
HE EVEN DOES HIS FRIES
IN SMALL BATCHES ALL DAY LONG.
WHY NOT BUY A SLICER?
I HAD ONE, AND I RIPPED IT
RIGHT OFF THE WALL.
SMALL DRIVE-IN FRY,
RIGHT?
HE WILL GET YOUR FOOD OUT
TO YOU IN FIVE MINUTES.
OR 10 TO 15.
(man) DEPENDS ON
HOW BUSY IT IS.
OH, I DON'T KNOW,
20, 25 MINUTES.
IT'S WORTH THE WAIT
EVERY TIME.
ALL RIGHT, CHICAGO.
MY JOB FOR YEARS AND YEARS
WAS WORKING THE BUSIEST SHIFTS
AT A VERY BUSY RESTAURANT.
TWO OF 'EM ON A DIET?
THEN PAT STARR MOVED
TO THIS JOINT.
I'VE BEEN HERE SINCE '99.
AND LESS THAN A YEAR LATER,
HE BOUGHT THE PLACE.
AND THIS WAS
HOW IT WAS SET UP THEN?
NOT AS FANCY,
IF YOU CAN BELIEVE IT.
AFTER FIXING IT UP HIS WAY...
WHAT'S UP, COOP?
POLISH CHICAGO?
THAT'S ME.
HE'S DOING THE DOGS HIS WAY...
ALL RIGHTY, ALL RIGHTY.
A LOT OF 'EM, CHICAGO-STYLE.
IT'S GOT TO BE
A VIENNA BEEF DOG,
OR ELSE YOU'RE IN BIG TROUBLE.
THEY DO IT REAL CHICAGO-STYLE.
VIENNA BEEF CHICAGO PRODUCT BUNS
ARE DESIGNED TO BE STEAMED.
SO WE HAVE YOUR BUN COOKING.
WE GOT THE DOGS HOT.
YOU WANT 'EM
ABOUT 170, 180.
YOU DON'T WANT 'EM SITTING AND
BOILING AWAY. THAT'S A NO-NO.
I'M GONNA GET
YOUR INGREDIENTS TOGETHER.
AND YOU CUT EVERYTHING
TO ORDER.
I--ON EVERYTHING.
GOT THAT HOT DOG
IN A STEAMED BUN,
TOMATO WEDGE,
ONIONS GO NEXT,
SOME OF THAT SPECIAL
UNIQUE GREEN RELISH.
IT'S GOT TO BE THAT WAY
IF YOU WANT A CHICAGO DOG.
COUPLE OF SPORT PEPPERS
AND THE CELERY SALT.
CELERY SALT.
AND MUSTARD--
THAT IS A CHICAGO DOG.
MMM. GREAT DOG,
NICE SNAP.
THE VEGGIES ARE FRESH.
BUN STEAMED PERFECTLY,
VERY GOOD.
WHERE YOU FROM?
CHICAGO.
HOW DID THIS STACK UP
IN THE WORLD OF CHICAGO DOGS?
VERY GOOD.
A LOT OF ONIONS,
LOTS OF MUSTARD.
THE SPORT PEPPERS,
THE RELISH
AND THEY PUT A WHOLE PICKLE
ON THERE, TOO.
IT'S ALL DONE RIGHT.
BUT IT ISN'T ALL HE'S GOT.
SO WHAT ABOUT MAKING ME
ONE OF THOSE DRIVE-IN DOGS?
GOT TO MAKE
THE COLESLAW FIRST.
THAT SHOULD BE
ANOTHER ADVENTURE.
MY WHOLE THING WITH COLESLAW
IS CONSISTENCY OF THE CUT.
OH, SO YOU REALLY
TAKE IT DOWN, HUH?
YEAH.
AN ONION HERE, NICE AND FINE,
REAL FINE CHOP THERE,
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
CELERY SALT.
THIS IS THE SUGAR.
SHAKE IT ALL TOGETHER,
GET IT ALL MIXED IN THERE.
ALL WE GOT TO DO NOW
IS PUT THE MAYO IN.
LOOKING GOOD.
WE MADE OUR COLESLAW.
SO WE GOT TO MAKE
A BATCH OF CHILI FOR YA.
GONNA CUT THAT ONION FRESH.
ABSOLUTELY. IT DEPENDS
WHAT I'M USING IT FOR.
IT MIGHT BE FINE
OR JULIENNE OR BIGGER CHUNKS.
MAYBE OLD JIM'S TOOTH
ISN'T WORKING SO GOOD,
AND WE GOT TO, YOU KNOW,
SOFTEN IT UP FOR HIM.
LET'S GET OUR PAN GOIN'.
WELL, I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL,
BUT HOW ABOUT JUST, LIKE,
A LITTLE CLICK LIGHTER?
I LOSE THOSE, AND THEY BREAK
DOWN, AND THEY'RE WORTHLESS.
GET SOME OIL IN THERE.
COVER 'EM. KEEP ALL THE YUMMY
ONION MOISTURE IN THERE.
GET SOME GARLIC GOING.
I JUST LOVE THAT GARLIC.
LITTLE HABANEROS,
CAREFUL WITH THAT STUFF.
WHOO-HOO. GROUND BEEF HERE,
SOME MORE.
SO REALLY NO MEASUREMENT STYLE,
JUST KIND OF EYEBALL IT,
LIKE, YOU FEEL GOOD.
YEAH, WELL, YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH YOU NEED.
PUT A LITTLE LID ON THERE
FOR JUST A SECOND.
LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
LITTLE CUMIN.
ARE WE GONNA BE EXPERIENCING
ANY CHILI POWDER IN THAT CHILI?
NOPE, JUST THE CUMIN.
NOW I'LL LET ALL THOSE JUICES
FLOW RIGHT INTO THE ONIONS,
AND I JUST PUT
CRUSHED TOMATO IN THERE.
I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
HOW THIS GOES.
ALL RIGHT, I GET
A LITTLE SPLASH OF WATER HERE,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA LET IT BOIL.
MMM.
YUMMY, YUMMY, YUMMY.
DUDE, WHY'S THIS CALLED
THE DRIVE-IN?
YOU KNOW, MY WIFE MADE IT UP,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHY.
WOW. IT'S GREAT.
I LOVE ONIONS IN MY SLAW.
FOR AS SIMPLE AS IT IS,
IT'S GOOD.
AND WE HAVE THAT ALSO
ON HASH BROWNS.
WE HAVE A NEW PIONEER
WHO PUTS IT IN AN OMELET...
I GOT THE T-BUD,
GOT THE SWEET FROM THE COLESLAW,
THE SPICY FROM THE CHILI.
ALSO ON FRENCH FRIES.
WHO'S GOT THE DRIVE-INS?
DRIVE-IN FRIES,
THEY'RE GOOD.
FOR A WHILE,
CAREFUL.
AND THAT'S THE FRYER?
THAT'S MY FRYER.
THIS DOESN'T HAVE
A THERMOSTAT.
I'M THE THERMOSTAT.
NOW YOU DOUBLE-FRY,
I WOULD ASSUME.
YES, EXACTLY.
OH, MAN, THEY'RE LOOKING GOOD.
THEY'RE LOOKING GOOD.
THAT'S RIGHT OUT OF
THE LEWIS AND CLARK CAMPING KIT.
ABSOLUTELY.
I CAN DO ALL THIS FOOD
WITH A HUBCAP
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROAD.
AT LEAST THAT
DOESN'T SCARE ME.
LITTLE SALT,
NOT TOO MUCH,
SOME CHEDDAR,
SOME MONTERREY JACK--
ALL RIGHT, TA-DA.
AHA.
ONE ORDER DOWN.
WE'RE GETTING
TO THE GOOD STUFF.
YOU'VE EATEN THE FRINGE.
WHAT IS THE GOOD SPOT?
OH, IT'S EVERYTHING
UNDERNEATH THERE.
THAT'S THE EPICENTER?
THAT'S THE EPICENTER.
CAN'T GO WRONG
WITH FRESH POTATOES.
I'M IMPRESSED.
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
AHH, LET'S SEE, YOU GOT MONEY,
PROBABLY 3 BUCKS.
HE'LL JUST GO,
"OH, THAT LOOKS LIKE 3 BUCKS."
$6.
HOW MANY PEOPLE
DO YOU RUN TABS FOR?
WELL, I JUST SAY
FINANCING'S AVAILABLE.
THE DEER?
THAT WAS A FOOD TRADE.
THAT WAS A BREAKFAST.
THE MARLIN?
TWO PHILLY CHEESESTEAKS.
SO PAWN SHOP/WIENERY.
LET'S MAKE A DEAL.
COMING UP,
I MAY HAVE TO SELL THE '67.
OH, THAT'S THE BEST THING.
TWO DOGS, BRO?
AT THE WIENERY
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
IT'S GOOD.
POLISH CHICAGO.
PAT STARR IS
A ONE-MAN DOG AND BURGER SHOW.
WHEN I'M WORKING GETTING
THEIR FOOD, MAKING THEIR COFFEE,
TAKING THEIR MONEY,
DOING THE DISHES--
(Guy) ALL AT THE SAME TIME?
WIENERY.
I WANT
A BACON CHEESEBURGER.
AND IF YOU HANG OUT
LONG ENOUGH...
HE MIGHT EVEN NAME
A BURGER AFTER YOU.
SALAMO'S HIS NAME.
OKAY, LET'S DO
THE SALAMO.
ALL RIGHT, GET A LITTLE BIT OF
GARLIC, LITTLE BIT OF HABANEROS.
AND, AGAIN, WE'RE GONNA CUT
EVERYTHING TO ORDER?
ABSOLUTELY.
AND ALL BURGERS
ARE HAND-FORMED.
GET IT ALL MIXED IN THERE.
ANGUS BEEF--ABOUT
1/3 A POUND, USUALLY.
NICE AND FLAT, I LIKE IT FLAT.
GET NICE AND DONE IN THE MIDDLE.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU WANT CHEESE
ON YOURS?
OH, YES, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT. THINK YOU WANT
LETTUCE AND TOMATO?
LET'S DO LETTUCE
AND TOMATO.
DOES THE KNIFE
HAVE A NAME?
LOOKS LIKE IT WAS DAVE'S
AT ONE TIME.
WHO WAS DAVE?
HE CAME IN, AND I GAVE HIM
A PHILLY CHEESESTEAK,
AND HE GAVE ME
A BUNCH OF NICE KNIVES.
VOILà, LE BURGER.
MMM.
GOT THE GARLIC,
DIDN'T GET MUCH HEAT.
OOH. THERE'S A LITTLE HEAT.
SURE YOU DIDN'T GET
THE SCOTCH BONNETS?
GOOD BURGER.
AND HOW MUCH?
4 BUCKS.
FOR 4 BUCKS, DUDE,
THAT KILLS ANY FAST FOOD.
THE FOOD IS GOOD. IT'S FAST.
IT'S INEXPENSIVE.
(man) AMAZING.
IT'S MY MAIN STAPLE.
WHAT'S THIS GUY INHALING?
SPICY, SPICY
ITALIAN COMBO.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S MAKE
THE ITALIAN COMBO.
ALL RIGHT.
WE GET THAT BUN STEAMING,
LOCALLY COOKED BUN.
NOW WE GOT TO GET
THE SAUSAGE GOING.
IT'S DEEP-FRIED
AND THEN GRILLED.
(whistles)
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL LET THAT COOK
UP FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S LIKE TENDERIZING
A CHICKEN BREAST
WITH A BASEBALL BAT.
I MAKE MY AU JUS TO ORDER
WITH GARLIC.
PUT ANY OIL
IN THAT GARLIC OR--
I PUT A HUNK OF BUTTER.
HUNK-A HUNK OF BUTTER.
SALT.
WE JUST WAIT TILL THIS GETS
BROWNED UP A LITTLE BIT,
THEN I PUT MY ROAST BEEF
RIGHT ON TOP OF THAT,
THIN-SLICED VIENNA ROAST BEEF
ALL FROM CHICAGO.
COVER IT,
LET THE GARLIC AND BUTTER
COOK INTO THE BEEF A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
CHEESE?
OKAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DIGGING FOR,
PAT?
THE HABANERO
FOR YA.
THIS IS A HONKER.
MM-HMM.
IT'S GOT THE FLAVOR,
THE TEXTURE, THE SALTINESS.
I MEAN, SAUTéING THE GARLIC,
HITTING THE MEAT IN THERE,
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
I GOT TO GIVE YOU PROPS ON THAT,
MAN. THAT IS--THAT WAS GREAT.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
HEY, BABY.
POLISH CHICAGO.
SIMPLE, INEXPENSIVE, FAST,
AND A FRIENDLY PLACE.
YOU GUYS WANT THE USUAL?
OKAY.
YOU OUT HERE, ZACKY?
I'M HOOKING UP ALL MY FRIENDS
WITH DELICIOUS MEALS EVERY DAY,
AND I KEEP IT CHEAP
BECAUSE THEY'RE ALL BROKE.
WHO WOULDN'T?
IT'S A UNIQUE PRODUCT.
MADE BY A UNIQUE GUY.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHAT DO YOU GUYS DO?
I'M A FLIGHT ATTENDANT.
SHOW ME WHERE
THE EXIT ROWS ARE.