I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
ENMOLADAS.
(speaks indistinctly)
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHAT IS
EXACTLY IN HERE?
UH, THAT'S A PIG TAIL.
A TASTE OF EVERYWHERE...
TRY SOMETHIN' NEW, AND I WAS
LIKE, ALL RIGHT, I LIKE THIS.
A FLORIDA JOINT
DOING AUTHENTIC JAMAICAN...
MMM!
CHINESE COOKIN'.
I HAVE RECIPES THAT'S BEEN
PASSED ON FOR YEARS.
OH, THAT I LIKE!
IN PITTSBURGH...
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE
SO WELCOME.
HOME COOKIN'...
ANOTHER LAMB SANDWICH,
RIGHT, MOM?
(woman) YES, MA'AM.
LEBANESE STYLE...
AND I'VE OPENED A LOT
OF PEOPLE'S TASTE BUDS UP
TO THE LEBANESE FOOD.
AND MAMA'S STILL DOIN'
THE GRAPE LEAVES HERSELF.
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GRAPE LEAF BREAK.
HOW'S THAT?
GOOD.
AND IN SALT LAKE CITY...
PUNTAS A LA NORTEÑA.
WHERE SERIOUS
MEXICAN COOKIN'...
KIND OF LIKE LET'S GO
TO GRANDMA'S HOUSE AND EAT.
MEANS ALL KINDS OF FLAVOR.
AND THEIR MOLES ARE GREAT.
YOU CAN'T GET A BAD ONE.
THAT'S SOME FANTASTIC
MOLE SAUCE.
HOLY MOLE!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU EVER FIND YOURSELF
CRUISIN' AROUND TOWN,
THINKIN', WELL, I WANT
SOME JAMAICAN FOOD,
YOU KNOW,
LIKE SOME STEWED OX-TAIL
OR MAYBE SOME CURRIED GOAT
OR BETTER YET, SOME STEWED PEAS
WITH PIG TAIL.
WELL, IF YOU'RE
IN KENDALL, FLORIDA,
YOU'RE IN LUCK.
YOU'VE GOTTA COME AND CHECK OUT
THIS JOINT--JAMAICA KITCHEN.
ON POINT!
LIPS BURNIN',
TONGUE BURNIN'.
YOU WANT SOME WATER?
UNH-UNH.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
THIS IS PRETTY MUCH
AUTHENTIC AS YOU CAN GET.
LIKE JAMAICA JAMAICAN?
YES, VERY JAMAICAN.
I'LL BE BACK TOMORROW TO GET
STEWED PEAS AND PIG TAILS.
YEP, SHE SAID "PIG TAIL."
IT'S QUITE GOOD.
OR HOW ABOUT SOME
STEWED OX-TAIL
OR SOME CURRIED GOAT?
WOW!
AND CHECK THIS OUT.
I'M HAVING
THE CHINESE CHICKEN.
IN A JAMAICAN RESTAURANT?
WHAT KIND OF FOOD
DO YOU CALL THIS?
JAMAICAN
AND JAMAICAN-CHINESE.
CURRIED SHRIMP
AND WHITE RICE.
IT'S THE FOOD CHERYL CHIN
AND HER HUSBAND ANTON
GREW UP ON IN JAMAICA...
HERE'S YOUR PEAS.
THANK YOU.
WHERE CHINESE IMMIGRANTS,
INCLUDING MANY
OF THEIR RELATIVES
HAVE BEEN SETTLING
FOR DECADES.
THREE OF MY GRANDPARENTS
ARE FROM CHINA.
MY OWN PARENTS WERE BORN
IN JAMAICA.
I HAVE RECIPES THAT'S BEEN
PASSED ON FOR YEARS.
I'M FROM JAMAICA ORIGINALLY.
I LOVE BOTH.
YEAH, WHY DON'T YOU CALL IT
JAMAICAN-CHINESE RESTAURANT
OUT THERE?
WE CONSIDER OURSELVES
JAMAICANS FIRST.
SO THEY'RE DOING
THE JAMAICAN CLASSICS...
THE STEWED OX-TAIL.
THIS IS ACTUALLY THE TAIL
OF A COW.
IT'S REALLY GOOD, THOUGH.
THIS IS THE ROLLS-ROYCE
OF BEEF.
COOKED UP BY HEAD CHEF
ALFRED KONG.
START WITH SOME WATER,
ALLSPICE.
THIS IS ALLSPICE,
NOT CHINESE FIVE SPICE.
NO.
GARLIC POWDER,
BROWN SUGAR.
CHICKEN BASE.
SALT, KETCHUP.
NOW?
SCOTCH BONNET PEPPER.
THREE OF 'EM. THAT'S WHY
YOU WEAR THE GLOVES.
GREEN ONIONS,
REGULAR ONIONS.
WE'RE ALMOST FILLING
OUR POT UP.
OH, IT'LL COME DOWN
WHEN IT STARTS BOILING.
TOMATOES, SOY SAUCE.
SOY SAUCE--
THICK SOY SAUCE, THOUGH.
EH?
THAT'S NOT LIKE
REGULAR SOY SAUCE, IS IT?
MUSHROOM SOY SAUCE.
OH, MUSHROOM SOY SAUCE.
AND BROWNING.
BROWNING CARAMEL--
OH, TO ADD SOME COLOR TO IT.
YES.
OKAY.
PUT IT ON THE FIRE.
PUT A LID ON IT AND LET IT
SIMMER FOR WHAT...
ABOUT THREE HOURS.
A 3-HOUR TOUR? OKAY, THEN YOU
BE GINGER. I'LL BE GILLIGAN.
(laughs)
IT'S LIKE THE NEVER-ENDING
POT SYMPHONY.
A LOT OF STEWING IS THE BASIS
OF JAMAICAN COOKING?
I WOULD SAY SO.
YOU CAN.
I DID.
YOU WILL.
I WILL.
OKAY. NOW IT'S
READY TO SERVE?
THIS LOOKS OUTSTANDING!
MMM! I LIKE THAT.
THAT'S KILLER.
ALL THAT FLAVOR
IN THE BONE
REALLY MAKES THAT
NICE AND DEEP AND RICH.
NICE AND TENDER--
JUST FALLS RIGHT OFF THE...
THE BONE.
THAT'S A NICE DISH.
IT'S TENDER,
VERY FLAVORFUL MEAT.
YOU GO SOME PLACES,
OX-TAIL IS LIKE EATING RUBBER.
BUT THIS IS VERY TENDER.
(Guy) AND THIS IS
THE CURRY OX-TAIL.
THIS IS THE CURRY.
OH, I WANT TO TRY
SOME CURRY OX-TAIL.
MMM, THAT'S IT!
THIS I COULD GET GOIN' ON.
OH, MAN!
YOU LOVE OX-TAIL.
THAT'S AWESOME
OX-TAIL!
I'M SALIVATING.
SPICY.
NOT TOO SPICY AT ALL.
I GARGLE WITH TABASCO.
MOST IS SPICY. THAT'S WHAT
JAMAICANS LIKE--SPICY FOODS.
I ALWAYS GET
THE SPICY BEEF PATTY.
ALMOST LIKE
A NATIONAL DISH
WHERE EVERYONE
IN JAMAICA EATS IT.
IT'S LIKE
A MEAT TURNOVER.
DON'T BE A WUSS.
GET A SUPER SPICY!
EXTRA? GIVE ME
SUPER SPICY!
SUPER SPICY! ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
THAT'S GOT, LIKE,
45 PEPPERS IN THERE.
THAT'S FANTASTIC!
THAT'S THE JAMAICAN
HAMBURGER EQUIVALENT.
THAT'S
A JAMAICAN HAMBURGER.
PRETTY MUCH,
THAT'S THE EQUIVALENT.
AND THE LITTLE
RED DOTS MEAN...
FOUR RED DOTS
MEANS SUPER HOT.
MEANS TROUBLE. MMM!
WHERE WAS I ON THIS--
IF YOU KEEP EATING IT...
HERE--HERE, GUY.
SORRY.
NO, NOT HOT.
I CAN TOTALLY HANDLE THIS.
(exhales deeply)
(laughs)
WHEW.
THAT'S LEGIT.
AND IF YOU WANT LEGIT...
WHAT IS
EXACTLY IN HERE?
UH, IT'S A PIG TAIL.
YEP, TAIL OF A PIG.
WITH STEWED PEAS, IF YOU
DON'T HAVE THE PIG TAIL IN IT,
I DON'T THINK
IT'S A FULL DISH.
I DON'T SEE YOU
JUMPIN' IN ON THIS.
I AIN'T HUNGRY.
"I AIN'T HUNGRY."
WELL, THAT'S ANOTHER ONE DOWN
HERE AT "DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"--
PIG TAIL--STRANGE.
YOU GET OUT OF THE MIND
THAT IT'S A PIG'S TAIL
AND YOU JUST ENJOY
THE FLAVOR.
VERY NICE.
THIS HAVE THE BEST FOOD,
AND IT'S NOT ONLY JAMAICA.
YOU CANNOT GO INTO A MAINSTREAM
CHINESE RESTAURANT
AND FIND DISHES LIKE THESE--
SUEY MEIN,
WHICH IS A NOODLE SOUP...
WITH BARBECUED PORK,
CHICKEN AND SHRIMP.
THE FOO GWA...
THAT'S BITTER MELON
STUFFED WITH SHRIMP AND PORK.
THIS IS CHINESE FOOD
THAT WE USED TO GET IN JAMAICA.
(Cheryl) PORK AND HAMCHOY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THAT'S PORK BELLY
WITH PICKLED MUSTARD GREEN,
THAT THEY'RE MAKING
BY THE GALLON.
SO WE PUT THE PORK IN,
A LITTLE SUGAR.
JUST 1 TABLESPOON?
YEAH.
OKAY.
A LITTLE SALT--
I EYEBALL IT.
SO ABOUT A TABLESPOON
AND A HALF.
YEAH.
OKAY.
MUSHROOM SAUCE.
MUSHROOM SOY.
BEAN SAUCE--
2 TABLESPOONS.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES...
THIS IS OYSTER SAUCE.
OYSTER SAUCE.
GINGER.
AND SINCE IT'S GONNA
SIT THERE AND STEW,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT CHOPPIN' IT UP.
RIGHT.
OKAY.
GREEN ONIONS.
ABOUT A CUP OF THOSE.
WHITE ONIONS, TOO?
WHITE ONIONS.
WATER?
WATER, YES.
THERE YOU GO, GUY.
HOLY GARLIC, BATMAN!
HOW MUCH?
THAT MUCH.
WELL, I HAVE JOHNNY GARLIC'S.
I GUESS THAT'S JAMAICA GARLIC.
SESAME OIL, BLACK BEANS.
HOW LONG DO WE PUT IT
ON THE STOVE FOR?
HOUR AND A HALF.
YEAH, I GOTTA
TELL YOU, ALFRED,
THIS IS THE MOST UNIQUE
LAYOUT OF FOOD I'VE SEEN.
REALLY?
OH, YEAH! I DON'T THINK
I CAN BUY THAT
AT MYERS RESTAURANT SUPPLY.
OH, WE MADE THAT.
NO!
YEAH, WE DID.
REALLY?
NOW I THICKEN IT UP
WITH SOME CORNSTARCH.
LIKE A ROUX?
LIKE A SLURRY?
YEAH, WHATEVER
YOU WANT TO CALL IT.
WHATEVER
I WANT TO CALL IT.
SO IN GO
THE PICKLED MUSTARD GREENS.
ANOTHER FIVE MINUTES.
ANOTHER FIVE MINUTES,
LET IT SET UP.
OH, IT'S LOOKIN' GOOD.
NOW YOU'RE TALKIN' TO ME.
THAT I LIKE!
SEE, THE SAUCE ON THAT
IS MONEY!
MMM!
BIG, DEEP, RICH FLAVOR--
THAT'S GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT TANGY,
AND AT THE SAME TIME
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET.
ALMOST EVERY DAY.
REALLY?
I ALWAYS LIKE TO HAVE
A HOME-COOKED MEAL.
WE ALWAYS LIKE
THE JAMAICAN DISHES,
'CAUSE I CAN'T
COOK THEM AT HOME.
SO YOU COME
AND GET YOUR FIX HERE.
RIGHT.
I LIKE IT.
ONE CURRIED GOAT.
YOU HAVE TO COME IN
AND TRY IT FOR YOURSELF--
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
WE CALLED IN
A HUMONGOUS ORDER.
AND YOU'RE
JUST SNACKING ON YOURS
WHILE YOU'RE WAITING
FOR THE ORDER.
RIGHT.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL.
I'LL KEEP THESE,
SEND 'EM TO MY MOM.
SHE'D BE SO PROUD OF ME.
I WOULDN'T EAT BROCCOLI,
BUT I'LL SCARF DOWN
A PIG TAIL. YEAH, MAKES SENSE.
UP NEXT...
AUTHENTIC
LEBANESE CUISINE.
GRAPE LEAVES
AND A LOT OF TABBOULEH.
MMM!
WE'RE HEADING TO PITTSBURGH
FOR A TASTE OF THE MIDDLE EAST.
YOU GET THE SAUCE,
GRILLED PEPPER. I LIKE IT,
'CAUSE IT'S INTERACTIVE--
EAT WITH YOUR HANDS.
♪♪
THREE YEARS AGO,
A WOMAN NAMED CRYSTAL JOSEPH
DECIDED TO OPEN A RESTAURANT
IN THE STRIP DISTRICT
OF PITTSBURGH.
NOW SHE'D NEVER BEEN IN
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS BEFORE,
SO SHE FIGURED SHE'D JUST GO
WITH THE HOME COOKING
SHE GREW UP WITH,
AND AT CRYSTAL,
THAT MEANS A LITTLE TASTE
OF THE MIDDLE EAST.
(speaks indistinctly)
GRAPE LEAVES
AND A LOT OF TABBOULEH.
MMM!
I WANT SOME MORE OF THAT!
I GOT THE COMBO. IT'S GOT KIBBEH
AND LAMB AND GRAPE LEAVES.
AUTHENTIC
LEBANESE CUISINE.
63--GRAPE LEAVES,
KIBBEH.
FROM AUTHENTIC
LEBANESE FAMILY RECIPES...
MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME
HOW TO MAKE IT.
YOU GOT IT READY?
AND WITH MOM TO RELY ON...
A LAMB SANDWICH
SET UP, MOM.
YEP.
WHEN CRYSTAL GOT A CHANCE
TO OPEN THIS JOINT,
IT JUST SEEMED TO MAKE SENSE.
I HAD NO CLUE WHERE I WAS GOING,
WHAT I WAS GOING TO DO.
70, 71...
I JUST HAD
A REALLY GOOD FEELING
WHEN I WALKED
INTO THIS BUILDING.
AND NOW THE FEELING'S ALIVE
FOUR YEARS LATER.
THE FEELING IS
DEFINITELY ALIVE.
(woman) THANK YOU.
YOU'RE SO WELCOME.
AND I'VE OPENED A LOT
OF PEOPLE'S TASTE BUDS UP
TO THE LEBANESE FOOD.
I WAS LIKE, TRY SOMETHING NEW,
AND I WAS LIKE, ALL RIGHT,
I LIKE THIS.
SHE SAID, "TRY MY LAMB."
I TRIED IT ONE TIME.
THAT'S ALL I GET NOW.
LAMB ON A ROD.
THE TASTE IS FANTASTIC.
(Crystal) WE'RE GONNA
MAKE LAMB ON THE ROD.
IS THAT WHAT IT'S CALLED?
LAHM MASHWI, YES.
WELL, IT'S EASY FOR YOU
TO SAY.
OH, YEAH?
SO HOW DO WE MAKE IT?
FIRST WE TAKE
A LEG OF LAMB.
BONE ROLLED AND TIED.
AND THEN WE CUBE IT UP.
HOW DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO MAKE THIS?
I LEARNED HOW TO CUBE IT FROM--
MY FATHER WAS A BUTCHER.
GONNA HELP?
OH, I THOUGHT IT WAS
ONE OF THOSE TRICK ONES,
LIKE--RIGHT?
I LIKE TO LEAVE THIS
ON THE COUNTER
AND THEN RUN IT THROUGH.
I LIKE TO LOOK
LIKE I'M DANGEROUS.
'CAUSE YOU'RE
LIKE, "WHAT?"
WHAT? HELLO!
I'M DONE WITH MINE.
NO, YOU'RE NOT. LOOK.
OH, YOU WANT IT
ALL THE WAY.
I WAS TRYING TO GIVE YOU
A VALUE-CONSCIOUS MEAL, SO--
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
(whistles)
THAT'S HALF THE LAMB.
IS IT NICE?
YEP.
EN GARDE!
LET'S NOT SWORD FIGHT.
OKAY.
NOW WE PUT 'EM IN HERE.
WE ARE GONNA MARINATE THIS
IN CHOPPED GREEN PEPPERS...
ONIONS.
ONION, LEMON JUICE.
NEXT IS OIL, CHOPPED GARLIC.
NOW HOW LONG DO WE WANT
TO LET THIS MARINATE FOR?
OVERNIGHT.
OVERNIGHT--FANTASTIC.
PUT IT ON THE GRILL HERE,
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
NICE SQUIRT BOTTLE THING.
YOU EVER SEEN "GUY'S BIG BITE"?
PUT OUR PEPPERS AND ONIONS
AND GARLIC IN HERE,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
YOU PUT A LITTLE SAUTé
ON THOSE.
WHEN DO THESE
GO ON, NOW?
YEAH. IN THE MEANTIME,
THAT'S DONE.
THAT ONE
MUST HAVE BEEN YOURS.
THIS ONE BACK HERE...
YEAH.
THE MORE
PREMIUM-LOOKING ONE?
SHOW ME THE MAGIC.
I HAVE A DELICIOUS
GARLIC SAUCE.
IS THAT NORMAL
IN LEBANESE FOOD,
THAT YOU GET THIS
LITTLE ACCOUTREMENT
EACH TIME?
EVERYTHING GETS THE PEPPERS
AND THE GARLIC.
IT LOOKS GREAT.
MY MOUTH'S WATERING.
IS IT?
WE'LL ADD SOME PITA BREAD,
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY FLAKES,
MAKE IT LOOK PRETTY.
YOU GET THE SAUCE,
GRILLED PEPPER.
AT LEAST THAT SKEWER'S
NOT SMOKING HOT.
SO YOU HOLD THE END
OF THE SKEWER WITH THE BREAD.
AH!
THEN YOU REMOVE IT
WITH THE BREAD.
MM-HMM!
THAT'S GREAT. MMM!
EXCELLENT!
LAMB'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
SO IS IT OKAY TO MAKE
LITTLE SANDWICHES OUT OF IT?
YES.
LITTLE SANDWICHES
ARE CALLED LITTLE BOSHES.
THIS IS DEFINITELY A FIRST
ON "TRIPLE-D"--
LITTLE BOSHES
IN PITTSBURGH.
I LIKE IT 'CAUSE IT'S
INTERACTIVE--
EAT WITH YOUR HANDS.
AH, YEAH.
PRETTY EASY TO EAT, HUH?
LAMB SANDWICH HERE.
A COMBO PLATTER WITH LAMB.
I TOOK SOME STUFF
FROM HER PLATE,
FROM HER PLATE
AND FROM HER PLATE.
MEDITERRANEAN QUESADILLA
THERE.
I HAVE
THE MEDITERRANEAN QUESADILLA.
IT'S A LITTLE MESSY,
BUT IT'S DELICIOUS.
MMM! WOW!
GREAT VEGETARIAN SANDWICH.
(man) I LOVE THE FETA,
THE DRESSING. IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S EXTREMELY GOOD.
(Guy) YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
TO EAT THAT WITH A FORK.
DID YOU READ THE LAW
AT THE FRONT DOOR
WHEN YOU CAME IN?
IT'S JUST REALLY DIFFERENT
FROM WHAT YOU COULD
USUALLY GET FOR LUNCH.
CHICKEN SALAD.
BUT SHE'S GOT THE LUNCH COUNTER
CLASSICS, TOO.
PHILLY CHEESE IS READY.
(Guy) WHAT DO YOU NORMALLY HAVE
BESIDES THE CHEESESTEAK?
THE CHEESESTEAK.
SHE NOT ONLY HAS
THE LEBANESE FOOD,
BUT SHE ALSO HAS
THE GREATEST HAMBURGER.
I'M HAVING THE HAMBURGER--
EXCELLENT.
(man) BACON CHEESEBURGER.
SO YOU REALLY GO LEBANESE
ON THAT.
YEAH, I DO.
BUT THE HEART
OF CRYSTAL'S MENU...
ANOTHER LAMB SANDWICH,
RIGHT, MOM?
YES, MA'AM.
IS STILL WHAT SHE LEARNED
FROM HER MOM.
ONE GRAPE LEAVES,
ONE KIBBEH.
THE KIBBEH IS REALLY GOOD.
ALMOST LIKE A MEATLOAF
OR MEATBALL.
BROWNED MEAT WITH PINE NUTS
AND SPICES IN IT--
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
IT'S LIKE
A LITTLE CRUSTY ACORN.
IT'S INCREDIBLY CRUNCHY.
THE PINE NUTS ARE
A NICE LITTLE ADDITION.
BUT IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR
AND TEXTURE. GOOD. DIFFERENT.
I TASTED THE KIBBLE TODAY,
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THEY KIBBEH, THE KIBBLE--
I MEAN, COME ON,
LET'S USE WORDS
THAT I'M FAMILIAR WITH.
BUT OF ALL CRYSTAL'S
FAMILY RECIPES...
MOM, WHAT DO WE NEED?
A LAMB, A GRAPE LEAVES...
YEAH, A GRAPE LEAVES.
THERE'S STILL ONE MOM INSISTS
ON DOING HERSELF.
WHAT IS YOUR HANDS-DOWN
FAVORITE ITEM ON THE MENU?
I'M A BIG FAN
OF THE GRAPE LEAVES.
I PICK THEM, WASH THEM
AND FREEZE THEM.
THAT'S RIGHT, RITA'S GETTING
ALL THE GRAPE LEAVES
FROM HER OWN BACKYARD.
GROUND CHUCK.
RIGHT.
PEPPER, SALT.
LEMON SALT.
AND THE TOASTED, COOLED-
IN-THE-ICE-WATER PINE NUTS.
RIGHT.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER DONE
THAT IN MY LIFETIME.
YOU LEARNED SOMETHING!
EVERY DAY.
GOOD.
A LITTLE DAB
IN THE CENTER.
JUST LIKE A...
THAT'S TOO MUCH.
OH, THAT'S
TOO MUCH FILLING?
UH-HUH, YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GRAPE LEAF BREAK.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
HOW'S THAT?
GOOD.
WHERE DID YOU GET
THE RECIPE?
WATCHING MY MOTHER.
WHAT ARE THESE CALLED?
IN LEBANESE
IT'S WARA ENAB.
THAT MEANS
"THE LEAF OF THE GRAPE."
WARA ENAB.
WHAT UP, ENAB?
VERY GOOD!
WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM IN HERE.
THIS IS THE CUMOON--ER, CUMIN.
SALT--A PINCH.
LEMON SALT AND THE WATER.
THAT KEEPS THEM
FROM FLOATING.
AND WHAT DO YOU SAY,
ABOUT 40, 45 MINUTES?
YES.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S HOW SHE COMES OUT.
(Rita) BE CAREFUL.
THEY'RE HOT! MMM!
WHAT A GREAT APPETIZER.
THE RICE IS TENDER,
MEAT'S FLAVORFUL.
YOU CAN PICK UP THE CUMIN.
WONDERFUL. I'M GLAD
YOU LIKE IT.
IT'S NOT WONDERFUL.
IT'S WARA ENAB.
WARA ENAB.
VERY YUMMY. I LOVE IT.
IT MAKES ME HAPPY.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE.
EXCELLENT PLACE,
EXCELLENT PEOPLE.
DID YOU THINK IT WOULD
TURN OUT THIS GOOD?
I HOPED THAT IT WOULD
TURN OUT THIS GOOD.
HOW WAS EVERYTHING?
WONDERFUL.
FULL OF YOUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY,
AND YOU'RE MAKING FOOD.
YES.
KIBBEH, GRAPE LEAVES,
LAMB ON THE ROD.
IF YOU WANT GOOD LEBANESE FOOD,
YOU COME TO CRYSTAL'S.
RIGHT HERE!
RIGHT NOW!
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
UP NEXT...
MMM.
WE'RE GOIN' WEST...
SOPA DE QUESO.
TO SALT LAKE CITY...
THERE'S SO MANY FLAVORS,
LIKE, COMBINED TOGETHER
THAT JUST MAKE IT POP
IN YOUR MOUTH.
FOR A MEXICAN CLASSIC
WITH EVERYTHING IN THE POT.
I'M GLAD I CAN'T REMEMBER
THE 9,000 THINGS YOU PUT
IN IT, BUT LOOK AT THAT!
MY FIRST JOB
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
WAS AT ROMAN'S
MEXICAN RESTAURANT IN FERNDALE.
NOW I LIVE IN CALIFORNIA,
SO YOU KNOW I LOVE MEXICAN FOOD,
BUT ESPECIALLY PLACES
THAT ARE DOIN' IT RIGHT,
LIKE THIS JOINT HERE
IN SALT LAKE CITY--
THE RED IGUANA.
NOW I HEAR THEY'RE MAKING
SEVEN DIFFERENT KINDS OF MOLE.
HOLY MOLE!
MOLE MEANS SAUCE, CONCOCTION.
IT'S AN INDIAN WORD.
IT'S A BASE SAUCE
OF THE CULTURE.
RIGHT.
AND A FAVORITE IN MEXICO...
PUNTAS.
FOR PARTIES
AND CELEBRATIONS.
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
IT'S LIKE YOU BRING MEXICO HERE.
THEY'VE BEEN DOIN' MOLES
HERE SINCE '85...
YOUR ENMOLADAS.
WHEN LUCY CARDENAS'S PARENTS
OPENED THE PLACE.
THEY'RE REALLY
TOP-NOTCH MOLES.
FOR TWO...
LUCY AND HUSBAND BILL
TOOK OVER A FEW YEARS AGO,
AND THEY'RE DOING SEVEN
OR EIGHT MOLES EVERY DAY...
YOU CAN'T GET A BAD ONE.
WITH NUTS, HERBS, CHILIES,
SPICES AND MORE.
I LOVE HOW THEY USE
THE MEXICAN CHOCOLATE
IN THEIR SAUCES.
LIKE THIS CLASSIC.
THAT'S YOUR MOLE,
THE KING OF MOLES.
RIGHT.
NOW HOW MANY GALLONS OF MOLE
ARE WE MAKING WITH THIS BUFFET,
THIS PLETHORA
OF INGREDIENTS HERE?
15.
15 GALLONS.
YES. WE'RE GOING
TO TAKE THE PEANUTS.
WE'RE GOING TO PUT THEM
IN THE POT HERE.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
WATCH 'EM FOR A WHILE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA THROW
A LITTLE TOAST ON 'EM.
YOU WANT TO BROWN 'EM.
SOME WALNUTS--MORE TOASTING.
I CAN'T HEAR ANYTHING!
I KNOW IT!
IT'S SO LOUD!
STOP THAT SENSELESS
STIRRING!
ALL THAT I KNOW IS
THAT WE TOAST 'EM HERE.
RIGHT IN HERE. WE'RE GONNA ADD
TORTILLAS TO THE HEATED OIL.
THE NATURAL THICKENER.
AND PUT THOSE ONIONS IN,
POBLANOS, JALAPEÑOS.
IN THE POOL?
IN THE POOL.
TOMATOES--
IT JUST KEEPS GOING.
TEAR IT UP--EPAZOTE.
IT'S AN HERB.
IT'S LICORICEY.
THE PARSLEY, THE CILANTRO.
WE PRACTICALLY HAVE DRUG
THE ENTIRE TURKEY
THROUGH THE GARDEN HERE.
RAISINS.
WELL, I HAVEN'T SOUS-CHEFFED
ON THE MOLE TRAIN IN A WHILE.
A LITTLE FRESH GARLIC.
A LITTLE.
THE PLANTAINS.
CORIANDER, THE ALLSPICE.
ALLSPICE, CINNAMON STICKS.
HERE GO THE CLOVES,
PEPPERCORNS, MARJORAM.
CUMIN, THE ANISE.
HOW MANY ITEMS
DO WE HAVE SO FAR?
PROBABLY ABOUT 18.
I CAN'T EVEN COUNT THIS BACK.
THIS IS THE THYME.
THYME, LAUREL LEAVES.
AVOCADO LEAVES.
YES.
THAT'S IT. WE HAVE
JUST GONE INTO A BOUNDARY
OF I HAVE NOT COOKED.
NEXT WE'RE GOING TO BE COOKING
WITH MY SOCK.
SALT AND CHIMOLE.
IT'S A SEASON PASTE WE ADD
TO ALL OUR MOLE.
ONLY TO MOLE?
ONLY TO MOLE.
SO IF YOU DON'T HAVE THIS,
YOU'VE GOT A BIG HO-LE
IN YOUR MOLE?
YES.
WE'LL JUST PUT IT
IN CHUNKS THERE, OKAY?
IT TASTES LIKE A FLAVORED
CHARCOAL BRIQUETTE.
OH, IT'S GOOD!
DO YOU WANT ME
TO STIR THIS?
SURE.
SO THAT'S NOT CHARCOAL.
THAT IS CHIMOLE.
SHOULD WE JUST GO AHEAD
AND PUT THESE IN?
I AM DOIN' IT.
WANT ME TO HELP YOU?
NOW I LOST COUNT.
OHH.
THE CHOCOLATE'S GOING IN,
AND YOU'RE ALMOST THERE.
WE LET IT SIMMER.
ANY MINUTE,
THIS IS GOING IN--
MY SUNGLASSES.
SO NOW WE HAVE
THE PASTILLA PEPPERS.
SO THESE HAVE BEEN DRIED
AND RECONSTITUTED IN WARM WATER,
BUT THE STEMS AND SEEDS--
OR MOST OF THE SEEDS--
HAVE BEEN TAKEN OUT OF 'EM,
BECAUSE THOSE
JUST WON'T BREAK DOWN.
RIGHT. THIS IS
CHILI MULATO.
IT'S A VERY BIG,
BEAUTIFUL...
(whistles)
BROWN--YOU CAN KINDA
SEE THAT. READY?
OKAY, SO ABOUT A CUP
OF CHICKEN BASE.
YEAH. HERE COMES
THE WATER.
WE'LL LET IT SIT HERE UNTIL IT
ALL SIMMERS TOGETHER,
MAYBE ABOUT 20 MINUTES
OR SO.
WELL, I'M GLAD I CAN'T REMEMBER
THE 9,000 THINGS YOU PUT IN IT,
BUT LOOK AT THAT!
IT'S REALLY COOL FOR YOU
TO SHARE THAT.
THAT'S A HECK
OF A FAMILY RECIPE.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
AND THEN WE BLEND IT.
I'M GONNA GET YOU, LIKE,
AN OUTBOARD BOAT MOTOR
FROM, YOU KNOW--
AND JUST HOOK IT UP HERE...
GET THAT AND IT'LL
MAKE IT A LOT QUICKER!
AND IT'S LIKE--
(imitates engine)
SO WE'RE GONNA PURéE IT
DOWN INTO BIGGER CHUNKS,
TRANSFER IT INTO A BLENDER,
GET ALL THAT DONE.
OKAY, SO WE GO OIL AND THEN WE
POUR THE MIXTURE INTO...
BLENDED MOLE.
THE BLENDED MOLE. OKAY.
A LITTLE SALT.
OKAY, NOW WE TASTE IT?
ON A BEAN-FILLED TORTILLA
CALLED AN ENMOLADA.
AND THAT IS...
IT'S NICE.
THE BEST WAY...
TO ENJOY IT.
TO APPRECIATE AND EXPERIENCE
YOUR MOLE.
YES.
MMM! THAT MOLE--
THAT IS--
THAT'S SOME FANTASTIC MOLE.
YOU GET THIS HEAT AND SWEET.
MY MOUTH IS--
YOU CAN PUT THAT
ON ANYTHING.
THANK YOU.
THERE'S SO MANY FLAVORS,
LIKE, COMBINED TOGETHER
THAT JUST MAKE IT POP
IN YOUR MOUTH.
(Lucy) YOUR ENMOLADAS.
AND REMEMBER,
THAT'S ONLY ONE.
LUCY'S MAKING ALL KINDS
OF MOLES.
THEY GO
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
THE GREEN SAUCE IS AWESOME
ON THE CHICKEN ENCHILADAS
WITH THE SOUR CREAM INSIDE.
MY FAVORITE IS
THE ENCHILADA SUIZAS.
THEY'RE TOPPED WITH A SPICY,
SWEET MOLE POBLANO
WITH CHILIES, FRUITS, NUTS
AND A TOUCH OF CHOCOLATE.
(man) MY FAVORITE DISH
IS THE MANGO ENCHILADAS.
IT'S A SPECIAL THAT THEY HAVE
ON FRIDAYS.
ALMOND MOLE.
LIKE ALMONDS--
THE NUTS?
YEAH.
MMM, THAT'S
FANTASTIC.
SERVED WITH ANOTHER
RED IGUANA SPECIALTY.
PUNTAS A LA NORTEÑA.
THAT'S CHOPPED SIRLOIN TIPS
WITH BACON,
JALAPEÑO, ONION AND TOMATO.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
WOW, THAT'S HOT!
IT'S LIKE A CREAMY SAUCE,
CREAMY SOUP--A GREAT MOLE,
A MOLE I DON'T THINK
PEOPLE WOULD EXPECT.
IT'S SORT OF CREAMY
BUT SPICY AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S GOT
A GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
YOU WANT HOT MEXICAN FOOD
IN UTAH, THIS IS THE PLACE.
THE MOLE AND A WHOLE LOT MORE,
LIKE HOMEMADE CHORIZO.
THAT IS A LOT OF SPICE.
THAT'S WORKIN'.
AND ANOTHER FAVORITE...
TACOS DON RAMON.
WHO'S DON RAMON?
MY FATHER.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MAYBE JUST
ONE MORE BITE.
♪♪
ENMOLADAS.
AT THE RED IGUANA
IN SALT LAKE CITY...
ENJOY.
THEY'RE SCRATCH-MAKING
ALL KINDS OF MOLE...
PUNTAS.
CLASSIC MEXICAN SAUCES...
MMM.
WITH EVERYTHING IN 'EM
FROM CHILIES TO CHOCOLATE...
YOU CAN ALMOST TASTE
THE HOMEMADE FEEL TO IT.
THE MOLES AND EVERYTHING ELSE
ON A MENU
FILLED WITH FAVORITES,
LIKE CHIMICHANGAS,
ENCHILADAS
AND A RED IGUANA SPECIALTY
CALLED TACOS DON RAMON.
WELL, IT'S THE ONLY THING
I EVER EAT WHEN I COME HERE.
BEEF AND CHORIZO--IT'S
LIKE A HOMEMADE CHORIZO,
MEXICAN SAUSAGE.
WHO'S DON RAMON?
MY FATHER.
DON--DON RAMON.
DON RAMON.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
FIRST AJO.
SO A LITTLE GARLIC.
ONION, PEPPER.
ONION. IS THAT
MEXICAN OREGANO?
YES. THYME,
MARJORAM, ALLSPICE.
ALLSPICE!
OKAY.
CINNAMON, CAYENNE,
PAPRIKA.
THEN NEW MEXICO
RED CHILI POWDER.
WHICH YOU SEE A LOT
USED UP HERE IN UTAH.
IT IS, YEAH.
WE'RE ADDING SALT,
LAUREL LEAVES,
VINEGAR. I'M--
WELL, AT LEAST THIS ISN'T
GONNA BE LACKING IN FLAVOR.
NO, NOT AT ALL.
YOU COULD USE STYROFOAM PEANUTS,
AND THIS WOULD TASTE GOOD.
AND THEN SOME OIL.
OIL.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT.
IT LOOKS LIKE PORK.
IT IS, COARSE GRIND.
OKAY.
WE'LL LEAVE IT
IN THE REFRIGERATOR
FOR A DAY.
THAT IS
A LOT OF SPICE.
OKAY. TACOS DON RAMON.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME CHOPPED SIRLOIN,
PUT IT RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
HOW MANY TACOS
YOU MAKIN'?
THREE.
(whistles)
YOU'RE GONNA EAT THREE OF 'EM.
THIS IS NEW MEXICO POWDER.
AND WHAT'S IN THAT?
GARLIC AND SALT.
I'M GONNA ADD THE CHORIZO
RIGHT ON TOP.
THIS IS MADE TO ORDER
EACH TIME?
YES, IT IS.
(whistles)
I HAVE MY TORTILLAS HERE
THAT I DIPPED
IN A LITTLE OIL...
SURE.
TO MAKE 'EM PLIABLE, RIGHT?
WE'LL JUST STICK THOSE THERE.
YOU WANT TO GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE CHORIZO JUICE ON THERE,
JUST TO KIND OF TURN THEM
A NICE REALLY PRETTY COLOR.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
WITH THE SEASONINGS IN IT.
YES.
THAT SMELLS INCREDIBLE.
WOW, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT OF LETTUCE
IN THE TACOS.
QUESO COTIJA.
OH, YEAH.
QUESO FRESCA,
QUESO ANYTHING.
OKAY.
THIS IS A LITTLE AVOCADO SALSA
THAT WE SERVE.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE PICO DE GALLO
ON THE SIDE.
LOVE, PEACE
AND TACO GREASE.
DELICIOUS.
CHORIZO'S FANTASTIC.
THE MEAT IS NICE AND TENDER.
THE CHEESE--
I DON'T HAVE ANY ON ME.
THAT'S A MIRACLE.
I HAVE TO GET AWAY FROM IT.
MAYBE JUST ONE MORE BITE.
PLEASE.
IT'S GOT DEPTH, BUT IT
ALSO HAS A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
BUT NOT TOO MUCH.
IT ALMOST TASTES LIKE IT HAS
A SEASONING ON THE TORTILLA
AND THEN DEEP FRIED.
EXCELLENT.
I COULD EAT, LIKE,
80 OF THOSE.
KILLER MEXICAN FOOD--
I MEAN, THAT SAYS IT ALL.
OH, THIS IS THE BEST PLACE
IN TOWN, HANDS DOWN.
NO QUESTION?
SALUD, RAMON,
AND LUCY, TOO.
WE'LL MAKE MOLE
ALL DAY!
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON "TRIPLE-D."
THYME.
IT'S, UH...
WE'RE ADDING
THE THYME.
WHOO!
(making crackling sounds)
DID THAT MAKE SENSE?
ARE YOU WITH ME?