HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THAT'S GOOD.
BRAIN FREEZE.
THAT WAS
A REAL HEADACHE FAST.
IN CHANDLER, ARIZONA...
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE MIXING UP IN THE BACK.
ALMOST 150 FLAVORS...
PUMPKIN.
PEACH.
CHOCOLATE CHIPOTLE.
BIRTHDAY CAKE GELATO.
OUR MOST POPULAR FLAVOR.
OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
MY LINE,
ALL DONE
THE AUTHENTIC ITALIAN WAY.
THESE ARE IMPORTED FROM SICILY,
GROWN IN THE LAVA OF MOUNT ETNA.
WANT SOME WINE WITH THAT MEAL?
LIKE A FRATERNITY HOUSE.
WHOO! BROTHER RAY.
IN VIRGINIA...
HERE YOU GO.
THE LEGENDARY DRIVE-IN...
IT'S A LANDMARK.
MAKING THEIR CONES
FROM SCRATCH,
SAME AS 100 YEARS AGO.
IS THIS REALLY
THE MACHINE, MR. DOUMAR?
ABSOLUTE FIRST MACHINE
WE EVER HAD.
AND IN NEW ORLEANS,
A HOMETOWN FAVORITE
YOU WON'T FIND ANYWHERE ELSE...
SWEET POTATO
SASSAFRAS PRALINE.
MMM. THAT IS SO ODD.
AND SUNDAES
IT TAKES A TEAM TO TACKLE.
I ALMOST GOT STABBED.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
WITH A NAME LIKE FIERI, YOU GOT
TO KNOW I'M A GELATO GUY.
YOU KNOW THAT
GREAT ITALIAN ICE CREAM?
SO WHAT'S "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES" DOING
IN CHANDLER, ARIZONA, AT A MALL?
WELL, THE STUFF THEY'RE MAKING
AT AUNT LENA'S
IS SO OUT-OF-BOUNDS,
I JUST HAD TO CHECK IT OUT.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
THE FLAVORS
ARE JUST SO UNIQUE.
HALF ROSE PETAL,
HALF CANNOLI.
MASCARPONE
AND AMARETTO.
TWINKIE GELATO.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE MIXING UP IN THE BACK.
AN AUTHENTIC ITALIAN RECIPE,
IMPORTED INGREDIENTS...
THEY'RE GROWN IN THE LAVA
OF MOUNT ETNA.
AND THE FRESHEST FLAVORS.
PEACH.
WATERMELON IN THE SUMMERTIME--
OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
MY LINE,
LET ME TRY
ROSE PETAL.
WE STEEP REAL ROSES.
WOW.
CHOCOLATE CHIPOTLE.
BIRTHDAY CAKE GELATO?
OUR MOST POPULAR FLAVOR.
RAY D'OTTAVIO'S
THE MAN BEHIND THE MIXER.
THERE YOU ARE, SIR.
I FELT I KNEW HOW TO MAKE
FLAVORS PEOPLE ARE GONNA WANT.
'CAUSE HE'S
A CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF.
I GRADUATED FROM
THE CULINARY INSTITUTE.
OF?
HYDE PARK.
REALLY?
BUT AFTER YEARS
ON THE EAST COAST,
RAY AND HIS WIFE CHERYL
WANTED A CHANGE.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU'D LIKE TO TASTE?
THEY PACKED UP THE KIDS...
HI, CAN I HELP YOU?
MOVED TO ARIZONA, AND THEN
STARTED SCOOPING UP GELATO.
THERE YOU ARE, SIR.
WE THOUGHT THIS IS GONNA BE FUN.
GONNA MAKE EVERYBODY HAPPY.
(woman) WE DID
A LOT OF EXPERIMENTING.
WALK DOWN THE GROCERY ISLE,
THAT'S A FLAVOR.
HE'S A VERY
SERIOUS CHEF.
START OF WITH MILK,
GRANULATED SUGAR,
DRIED MILK POWDER,
LOCUST BEAN
AND GUAR GUM
SO THAT IT HOLDS TOGETHER.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
NAIL THIS THING.
RIGHT.
BLEND IT ALL TOGETHER.
HE'LL HOLD IT FOR A DAY
WHILE THE FLAVORS DEEPEN.
LET'S GET THIS
IN THE MACHINE.
THEN THE LIQUID GOES IN,
AND THE GELATO COMES OUT.
THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S NOT AS HEAVY.
IT'S GOT BETTER FLAVOR.
SO MUCH LIGHTER THAN ICE CREAM,
NOT AS HEAVY AS CUSTARD.
'CAUSE IT'S GOT LESS FAT
AND LESS AIR--
AND IT'S GOT EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT RAY'S THROWING IN.
HE USES ALL-NATURAL FRUITS
AND FLAVORS.
VERY UNIQUE,
VERY ORIGINAL.
IS THAT GINGERBREAD MAN
OVER THERE?
YES, THAT'S OUR GINGERBREAD.
FRESH GINGERBREAD.
OHH.
MADE RAY'S WAY,
WITH A SCRATCH-BAKED
GINGERBREAD CAKE
RIGHT IN THE MIX.
TRY SOME OF THAT--ONLY BECAUSE
Y'ALL WANT ME TO.
MY NEW FAVORITE.
LET ME TRY TIRAMISU.
JUST LIKE IN ITALY.
BRANDY, MARSALA WINE,
MASCARPONE CHEESE.
NOW THAT'S FREAKING ME OUT.
IT HAS THE COMPLEXITIES.
IT HAS THE DIFFERENT LAYERS OF
FLAVOR. IT'S NOT JUST ALL BLAH.
CAN I HAVE
A SMALL CANNOLI?
AND LOOK AT THIS. YOU ACTUALLY
HAVE A CANNOLI THAT YOU MAKE.
DID YOU WORK FOR MACY'S
IN THE WINDOW DEPARTMENT?
(Ray) WE WANT TO USE
ALL THE FRESH INGREDIENTS
THAT REALLY GO
INTO A CANNOLI.
THIS IS IMPASTATA CHEESE,
A CREAMIER RICOTTA CHEESE.
MMM.
VANILLIN POWDER--
CONCENTRATED 50 TIMES
THE STRENGTH OF REGULAR VANILLA.
CINNAMON OIL.
I USED TO MAKE
TOOTHPICKS WITH THIS
WHEN I WAS A KID.
WOW.
IT SAYS YOU'RE GOING
40 MILES AN HOUR, RAY.
HOLY MOLY,
LIQUID CANNOLI.
IF I ATE THAT,
I'D BE ROLY-POLY.
I'LL BE HERE
ALL WEEK.
START THE MACHINE,
AND THEN WE ADD
THE CANNOLI SHELLS ONTO IT,
AND WE ADD CHOCOLATE.
THAT IS CRAZY
THAT IN ICE CREAM
IT TASTES LIKE IT,
AND THEN WHEN YOU GET THE CRUNCH
OF THE CANNOLI RIGHT THERE--
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY MORE
OF THESE I CAN EAT, THOUGH, MAN.
BUT YOU GOT
TO SAVE ROOM FOR PIE.
SO NOW AN APPLE PIE.
WE JUST SLIDE IT RIGHT IN.
WHOA, THERE WE GO.
AND THE CRUST IS THE EXACT
PROPORTION TO PIE THE FILLING.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
MAKING FISH STEW
BY JUST STICKING
THE BLENDER IN THE TANK.
HOW MANY HAMSTERS
RUN THIS?
I THINK--
IS IT FOUR NOW?
THAT'LL JUST
PUT YOU TO SLEEP.
I OFTEN SIT IN MY GELATO
CHAIR AND DO GO TO SLEEP.
THIS IS
YOUR GELATO CHAIR?
IT'S MY GELATO CHAIR.
WHAT ARE YOU WATCHING, HONEY?
APPLE PIE STATION.
SO I SEE IT'S STARTING
TO GET CREAMY IN THERE.
OKAY, GRAB
THAT SPATULA.
GO FROM THIS SIDE
TO THAT SIDE, CUT IT OFF...
THERE I GO.
AND I'D STAND IT UP.
YEAH.
OH. OH.
WHOA.
THIS REMIND YOU
OF "I LOVE LUCY"?
I UNDERSTAND
THE SEAT NOW, RAY.
WHAT IS THAT
OVER THERE, RAY?
MMM. DID HE SEE IT?
BEAUTIFUL.
MMM.
WE WEREN'T SUPPOSED TO EAT
OFF THE SPOON? THAT'S GOOD.
WHEN YOU EAT
APPLE PIE AND ICE CREAM
AND YOU GET THAT LITTLE SLURRY
IN THE BOTTOM OF THE BOWL...
RIGHT.
AND IT'S LIKE YOU COULD DRINK
THE APPLE PIE AND ICE CREAM?
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS.
THAT'S GOOD.
JUST LIKE EATING AN APPLE PIE.
FANTASTIC.
THE FLAVORS
KEEP YOU HOPPIN'.
AND RAY KEEPS
INVENTING NEW ONES--
NEARLY 150 SO FAR.
DO YOU GET THE SAME FLAVOR EACH
TIME YOU ROLL IN, OR DO YOU--
OH, NO.
NO.
HAVE TO TRY
ALL OF 'EM.
HE'S PUTTING OUT
ABOUT 30 A DAY...
SMALL CANNOLI
AND A SMALL LEMON.
AT LEAST
A DOZEN FRESH FRUIT.
BLOOD ORANGE.
REAL BLOOD ORANGE IN THERE?
YES, SIR.
WOW. THAT'S LIKE
TURBO SHERBET.
IS THAT STRAWBERRY?
FRESH STRAWBERRY.
ALL OUR FRUIT FLAVORS ARE FRESH.
MMM.
AND HE MEANS REALLY FRESH.
LEMONS
FROM MY OWN TREES.
LIKE ITALIAN ICE
GONE WILD.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ROASTED ALMOND AND FIG.
WITH MY OWN FIGS
FROM MY GARDEN.
EVERY TIME YOU COME IN HERE,
THERE'S A NEW FLAVOR.
FOR CHINESE NEW YEAR, WE MADE
RED BEAN PASTE GELATO.
MMM!
I'M GONNA FIND, LIKE, SPAGHETTI
AND MEATBALL GELATO, AM I?
NO, BUT YOU WILL FIND
REGGIANO-PARMIGIANO.
GELATO.
YES, SIR.
AND HEY, WHAT GOES
BETTER WITH CHEESE...
MERLOT.
WINE IN ICE CREAM?
ABSOLUTELY.
SO WE'RE GONNA START WITH WATER.
TO IT, WE WANT TO--
SUGAR.
THIS IS OUR BASE.
SO THIS
IS A DIFFERENT BASE.
YES, BECAUSE THE ALCOHOL
WON'T FREEZE PROPERLY.
SO THIS IS GONNA BE KIND OF
THE ICY GELATO, AS WE KNOW IT.
THIS IS GONNA BE
SORBETTO.
NOW THE WINE?
NOW THE WINE.
LIKE A FRATERNITY HOUSE.
WHOO! BROTHER RAY.
I'M IN
THE APPRENTICESHIP.
SMELLS GOOD. HEY, YOU KNOW
WHY THIS SMELLS SO GOOD?
THIS IS
SONOMA COUNTY WINE.
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU KNOW SONOMA COUNTY--
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA?
ONLY THE BEST.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
PUSH THE BUTTON?
YES, SIR.
NOT A HUGE FAN
OF THAT BEGINNING
NOISE SOUND.
NO, HUH?
I THINK
THE NON-MILKY BASED ONE'S
A LOT EASIER TO GET OFF
OF THERE, RAY.
OKAY, IF YOU SAY SO.
YOU WANT TO STACK IT HIGH
FROM THE FRONT
SO IT LOOKS VERY NICE.
YOU CAN SEE IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE YOU GO.
I BELIEVE IN EATING BIG.
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
NICE AND CREAMY AND COLD.
OH, IT'S AWESOME.
WANT TO TRY IT?
BEST FLAVORS EVER.
OLD-SCHOOL INGREDIENTS...
REMINDS ME
OF SICILY IN ITALY.
IN THE HANDS OF A DUDE
WHO KNOWS HOW TO USE 'EM.
IT WAS AMAZING.
I LOVE IT.
THE GREAT THING IS YOU CAN COME
IN EVERY SINGLE WEEK
AND GET A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT FLAVOR.
PART OF MY TONGUE GOT STUCK
ON THE BOTTOM OF THAT.
UP NEXT...
THANK YOU.
WE'RE HEADING TO VIRGINIA.
(man) THERE'S
A WARM CONE
AND A COLD ICE CREAM--IT'S
A NICE COMPLEMENT TO EACH OTHER.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR MORE THAN 100 YEARS.
HEY, THAT'S GONNA BE
A GOOD ONE.
THAT'S OKAY
FOR A ROOKIE?
YOU EVER BEEN ON A ROAD TRIP
WITH THE FAMILY AND EVER WONDER,
WHERE'S THE BIGGEST BALL
OF TWINE OR THE DEEPEST CAVE?
AND I KNOW A LOT OF KIDS
HAVE SAID,
"DAD, WHERE WAS
THE ICE CREAM CONE INVENTED?"
WELL, TODAY ON TRIPLE D,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE YOU THERE--
DOUMAR'S--NORFOLK, VIRGINIA.
THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT.
HI, HOW ARE Y'ALL
TODAY?
CHOCOLATE CONE
AND A NUT CONE.
THANK YOU.
BEST WAFFLE CONE
IN THE TOWN.
IS THIS REALLY
THE MACHINE, MR. DOUMAR?
YES, SIR.
THAT'S--
THE ACTUAL ONE.
ABSOLUTE FIRST MACHINE
WE EVER HAD.
AND AL DOUMAR'S FAMILY SAYS
THEY'RE THE ONES
WHO STARTED IT ALL.
MY GREAT UNCLE STARTED
THE ICE CREAM CONE.
THAD DOUMAR SAYS
HIS GREAT UNCLE ABE
FIRST PUT ICE CREAM
INTO A ROLLED-UP WAFFLE
AT THE ST. LOUIS WORLD'S FAIR
IN 1904.
HE OPENED UP IN NORFOLK
IN 1907,
AND DOUMAR'S HAS BEEN
A VIRGINIA STAPLE EVER SINCE.
MY MOTHER IS 83.
SHE USED TO HANG HERE.
SHE STILL COMES.
TWO LIMEADES
WITH SHERBET.
AND THESE DAYS, THAD IS KEEPING
THE FAMILY TRADITION ALIVE.
CHOCOLATE SODA.
AND HERE WE GO.
THAT'S GOOD.
WHEN YOU'RE IN NORFOLK, YOU GOT
TO STOP BY DOUMAR'S, SO WE--
THAT'S KIND OF
HOW IT WORKS?
YEAH.
THAT WAS
A REAL HEADACHE FAST.
IT'S A STAPLE IN VIRGINIA.
I CAN EAT UP HERE ALL THE TIME.
(woman)
IT'S A LANDMARK,
AND IT'S THE DRIVE-IN
IN THE TRADITIONAL SENSE.
HERE YOU GO.
WHERE THEY'RE
DOING EVERYTHING
THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN DONE...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
FROM THE CLASSIC MILK SHAKES...
WE MAKE
ALL OF OUR SYRUP.
AND THE CAR HOP SERVICE...
COMIN' RIGHT UP.
TO THE HANDMADE CONES
THAT STARTED IT ALL...
WE COME HERE AND WATCH 'EM
COOK 'EM IN THE EVENINGS.
AND IT SMELLS
LIKE WAFFLES
ALL DOWN THE STREET.
IT SMELLS SO GOOD.
FROM THE SAME RECIPE.
START WITH 3 OUNCES
OF MILK AND BUTTER,
3 OUNCES
OF VANILLA FLAVORING,
POUND OF SUGAR,
2 POUNDS OF FLOUR
AND 30 OUNCES OF WATER.
30 OUNCES OF WATER.
AND THIS IS WHAT
IT GETS MADE IN EACH TIME.
EVERY TIME, RIGHT HERE.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S IT. THAT'S ALL
THERE IS TO IT.
NOW DO YOU LET IT CHILL,
LET IT SET UP?
WE CHILL IT
GENERALLY OVERNIGHT.
IT'S READY TO GO
THE NEXT MORNING.
AND THEN AL DOUMAR
MAKES THE CONES--200 A DAY.
SEE MY THUMB,
AND THERE IT IS.
RIGHT.
IS THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S OKAY
FOR A ROOKIE?
TURN IT OVER.
GO BACK TO THIS ONE HERE.
DOUGH.
FLY.
HUH?
OH, DO THIS ONE,
RIGHT HERE.
LIKE THE CONE GAUNTLET.
IN THE PAN OVER HERE.
CAN I EAT IT?
YEAH,
YOU CAN EAT IT.
THAT'S CRUNCHY-MUNCHY
RIGHT THERE.
THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
ABOUT THE CRUNCH AND THE TASTE
AND THE FRESHNESS.
NOW THE OTHER CONES
HAVE PRESERVATIVES.
HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU EAT A DAY?
OH, I EAT TWO OR THREE
IN THE MORNING.
HEY, THAT'S GONNA BE
A GOOD ONE.
IT'S A HANDMADE RECIPE.
IT'S VERY FRESH AND IT'S CRISP,
AND IT'S A WARM CONE
AND A--AND A COLD ICE CREAM.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY--IT'S A NICE
COMPLEMENT TO EACH OTHER.
I LIKE TO GET
A BUTTER PECAN.
ORANGE SHERBET
IN A CONE.
OR A CONE IN JUST ABOUT
ANYTHING ELSE.
NEXT ON THE HIT PARADE
IS OUR STRAWBERRY WILLY.
"NEXT ON
THE HIT PARADE."
VANILLA ICE CREAM,
OUR CRUSHED-UP CONE CHIPS.
SO THESE ARE THE CONES
THAT DIDN'T MAKE IT.
STRAWBERRIES ON THERE,
A LITTLE STRAWBERRY SYRUP.
MMM.
I LIKE STRAWBERRY.
THAT'S GOOD.
THE CONE ON THERE
IS KIND OF LIKE
CROUTONS ON A SALAD.
YEAH, THEY'RE
REALLY GOOD.
BUT THIS IS JUST
SWEET AND FROZEN.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU WOULD LIKE THIS.
OR THE SAME THING
DONE IN CHOCOLATE.
THEY CALL IT THE RINGO.
GREAT DISH. CHOPPED-UP CONE,
CHOCOLATE FUDGE--
MAN, CAN'T BEAT IT.
THEY'VE GOT THE CLASSICS...
MAN, THAT THING'S GOOD.
BANANA SPLIT, HOT FUDGE SUNDAE.
THERE'S
A BANANA FUDGE CAKE SUNDAE,
THE HAWAIIAN SUNSET--
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
CAN'T BEAT THE ICE CREAM,
AND THIS--THIS IS PERFECT.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR OVER 15 YEARS.
HOW LONG YOU FOLKS
BEEN COMING HERE?
OH, OUR WHOLE LIVES.
AND NOT JUST FOR DESSERT.
CHEESEBURGERS WITH MAYONNAISE
AND ONE HEAVY ON THE SLAW.
SIMPLE CHEESEBURGER.
VERY TASTY.
IT'S WORTH COMING
ALL THE WAY FROM CONNECTICUT.
AND SCRATCH-MADE BARBECUE PORK.
I CAN EASILY SMOKE DOWN
ABOUT 19 OF THOSE.
BEST BARBECUE EVER.
CAN'T GET THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
(laughter)
YOU CAN ONLY GET IT HERE.
ALONG WITH THIS
DOUMAR SPECIALTY.
YOU ALWAYS GET
A LIMEADE.
ASK EVERYBODY,
ALL THE CARS--
LIMEADE.
THEY'LL ALL HAVE
A LIMEADE.
LIMEADE IS
OUR SIGNATURE DRINK.
SQUEEZE YOUR LIME, A LITTLE
SPRAY OF CITRIC ACID
IN EACH ONE OF THESE.
AND WE DON'T MAKE THIS
AHEAD OF TIME IN, LIKE,
A 50-GALLON DRUM?
OH, NO.
EACH ONE
IS DONE INDIVIDUALLY.
THEN WE ADD SUGAR
WITH OUR SIMPLE SYRUP...
RIGHT.
SUGAR WATER.
WOW. AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE?
THERE'S YOUR LIMEADE.
IT'S OUR BEST-SELLING DRINK
IN THE HOUSE.
OH, THAT'S REFRESHING.
ISN'T THAT GREAT?
YOU YOU GET
THE LIME FLAVOR,
BUT NOT THE HARSH ACIDITY
OF THE LIME.
IT TASTES LIKE A SODA.
ABSOLUTELY.
BUT IT'S ALL
MADE BY HAND.
CORRECT.
YOU CAN GET IT
WITH LIME SHERBET, TOO,
OR THE SHERBET WITH ICE CREAM
FOR A LIME FREEZE--
OR AN ORANGE FREEZE.
THAT ONE TAKES A LOT OF PEOPLE
BACK TO WHEN THEY WERE KIDS.
MMM.
ORANGE FREEZE
TASTES LIKE A DREAMSICLE.
YOU GET FOUR DIPS OF ICE CREAM,
ADD A LITTLE SUGAR WATER,
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF CARBONATED WATER.
NOW SET IT HERE
ON THE BEATER.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
SOME VANILLA MIX TO IT.
AND THEN YOU JUST
STIR IT THROUGH. ALL RIGHT.
OHH.
GREAT. DOESN'T IT
REMIND YOU OF THE DREAMSICLE?
OHH--JUST SEMI-MELTED
WITHOUT THE STICK.
RIGHT.
YOU GET A LITTLE OF THE ORANGE,
OF THE CREAMINESS TO IT.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD--
THAT'S CREAMY.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
WHENEVER WE HAVE FRIENDS AND
GUESTS COME FROM OUT OF TOWN,
IT'S ONE OF THE FIRST PLACES
WE COME TO.
IT'S JUST A COOL PLACE.
IT'S A NORFOLK TRADITION.
ASK ANYBODY WHERE DOUMAR'S IS
AND THEY CAN'T TELL YOU,
YOU KNOW
THEY'RE A TOURIST.
(woman) EXACTLY.
I HAVE BEEN COMING HERE
SINCE I WAS A LITTLE GIRL,
AND I'VE STARTED BRING MY SON
SO HE CAN EXPERIENCE IT.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
SINCE I WAS A KID.
SAME ICE CREAM, SAME SERVICE--
THE PLACE IS GREAT.
NOW THERE MAY BE SOME FOLKS
WHO'LL TRY TO TELL YOU
IT WAS SOMEONE ELSE WHO
INVENTED THE ICE CREAM CONE,
BUT DON'T TRY TELLING THAT
TO THE FOLKS AT THIS JOINT.
(Thad) I THINK MY GREAT UNCLE
WOULD BE PROUD.
WE'RE STILL
CARRYING ON HIS LEGACY.
ALL RIGHT, HERE YOU GO.
DO THIS ONE.
OKAY.
OKAY, SO UP, OVER...
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
ROLL.
LIKE THAT.
THAT'S DAMN GOOD.
PUT IT UP THERE.
DAMN GOOD, HE SAID.
NEXT STOP--NEW ORLEANS...
EAT ICE CREAM,
BE HAPPY.
FOR SOME LOCAL FLAVOR...
SAFFRON PISTACHIO.
(man) AVOCADOS AND CREAM.
BLUEBERRY MOJITO.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
THEY KEEP PILING HIGH.
THERE YOU ARE, HUH?
HERE IN THE UPPER GARDEN
DISTRICT OF NEW ORLEANS,
A COUPLE OF HIGH SCHOOL BUDDIES
GOT TOGETHER
AND STARTED
DOING ICE CREAM RIGHT.
NOW THEY'VE GOT
OVER 400 FLAVORS,
AND SOME WITH A TRUE
NEW ORLEANS TWIST.
SO I FIGURED I JUST GOT TO STOP
AND CHECK OUT
THE CREOLE CREAMERY.
MINT CHOCOLATE CHIP.
THERE YOU GO.
CUP OF COTTON CANDY.
THANK YOU.
HOW'S YOUR ICE CREAM?
DELICIOUS.
IT'S AWESOME.
CAN I HAVE A BITE
OF YOUR ICE CREAM?
IT'S FRESH.
REALLY CREAMY.
HOMEMADE AND SERVED UP BIG.
I'D LIKE
A SKY SCRAPER.
THERE YOU GO.
A RED, WHITE & BLUEBERRY--
DELICIOUS.
(man) THANK YOU.
(man) ENJOY.
REALLY GOOD.
I'VE NEVER SEEN 3/4
OF THESE FLAVORS BEFORE.
GRILLED PINEAPPLE.
BLUEBERRY MOJITO.
SWEET POTATO
SASSAFRAS PRALINE.
MMM. THAT IS SO ODD.
SO WILD AND STRANGE.
AND REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT'S VERY NEW ORLEANS.
THANK YOU.
JUST LIKE THE GUYS
WHO MAKE IT...
LEMON CREAMSICLE'S
GOING BACK OUT.
LIFE-LONG LOCALS
DAVID BERGERON...
THERE YOU GO.
AND BRYAN GILMORE.
YOU WERE BUDDIES
IN HIGH SCHOOL?
WE WORKED TOGETHER IN AN ICE
CREAM PARLOR WHEN WE WERE YOUNG.
BRYAN STARTED OUT
INVENTING HIS OWN FLAVORS
IN HIS OWN KITCHEN AT HOME.
SAFFRON PISTACHIO,
PLEASE.
I WAS MAKING THINGS LIKE AVOCADO
AND PEAR CHAMPAGNE SORBETS,
SO WHEN MY BUDDY DAVID
DECIDED TO DO THIS,
HE ASKED ME TO COME ON.
(David) I KNEW HE WAS
REALLY GOOD IN THE KITCHEN,
REALLY CREATIVE,
SO I'VE BEEN ABLE TO JUST TURN
IT OVER TO HIM IN THE BACK.
THERE YOU ARE.
WHILE DAVID PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER UP FRONT...
THIS IS
THE TCHOUPITOULAS SUNDAE.
NAMED AFTER A STREET
IN NEW ORLEANS
AND A LOCAL FAVORITE.
PEOPLE COME IN,
AND THEY PICK EIGHT FLAVORS
OF ICE CREAM, EIGHT TOPPINGS.
I WANT TO START OFF
WITH COFFEE,
SWEET POTATO
SASSAFRAS PRALINE,
LAVENDER HONEY. WE GOT TO DO
THE RED VELVET CAKE.
SPANISH GRAPEFRUIT,
GRAND MARNIER,
CRèME BRûLéE.
OH, SALTED CARAMEL
GELATO?
THAT'S KILLER.
THAT'S SOMETHING
TO WRITE HOME ABOUT.
THE LAVENDER--FANTASTIC.
IS THAT THE HAM SANDWICH?
SO TOPPINGS.
BANANAS.
BANANAS ARE GOOD.
I'M CALLING IN THE AUTHORITY--
MY 11 YEAR OLD.
(Hunter) Caramel,
uh, chocolate...
CHOCOLATE CHIPS
AND GUMMY BEARS.
Cookies on it.
SOME COOKIES
AND SOME LITTLE M&M'S.
OH, YOU SHOULD SEE THIS, MAN.
HE'S PUTTING THE CHERRY ON TOP.
IT'S MY LONG-DISTANCE
TCHOUPITOULAS. SPELL THAT.
(girls) THANK YOU.
(Guy) NOW HOW LONG
DOES IT TAKE
THE AVERAGE PERSON
TO FINISH ONE OF THOSE?
(David) I'D SAY AVERAGE,
TWO, TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
I'M TRYING.
THE SUCCESS RATE
IS 5% TO 10%.
REALLY?
ARE YOU GUYS SURE
YOU CAN EAT THIS WHOLE THING?
(boys) YEAH.
HAVE YOU DONE
ONE OF THESE BEFORE?
YEAH.
FIVE, FOUR,
THREE...
I ALMOST GOT STABBED.
THERE YOU GO.
BUT IF YOUR IDEA OF A PARTY
IS MORE
THE ULTIMATE CHOCOLATE THING,
THEN GET THIS BABY...
IT'S EXCELLENT.
OR SOMETHING CALLED
THE SKY SCRAPER.
IT'S HOT FUDGE, VANILLA,
MORE HOT FUDGE,
CHOCOLATE,
CARAMEL RIGHT HERE,
SOME OREOS,
COOKIES & CREAM ICE CREAM,
FUDGE ON TOP,
SOME MORE OREOS.
WOW.
THERE YOU ARE, HUH?
WHAT A WELL-DIGGER.
AND REMEMBER, ONCE YOU DIG
THROUGH THE TOPPINGS,
THE ICE CREAM ITSELF
IS WORTH THE WORK...
MMM.
SCRATCH-MADE BY A GUY WHO
TAUGHT HIMSELF HOW TO DO IT.
ODDEST FLAVOR
YOU'VE EVER MADE.
ROASTED BEETS
WITH ORANGE ZEST
AND FROZEN
CREAM CHEESE CHIPS...
OOH.
IN A VODKA REDUCTION.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT SOME
OF THEIR UNIQUE FLAVORS,
LIKE
THE LAVENDER HONEY?
I THINK
THEY'RE PRETTY AWESOME.
THE LAVENDER IS JUST RIGHT.
YOU CAN TASTE THE HONEY.
THEY GOT
EVERYTHING DEAD-ON.
VERY CREATIVE.
LIKE THIS ONE--
TOTALLY NEW ORLEANS.
SWEET POTATO
SASSAFRAS PRALINE.
SO WHAT GOES IN?
SWEET POTATOES?
FILé.
GUMBO.
GROUND-UP
SASSAFRAS LEAVES.
GROUND SASSAFRAS LEAVES.
EXACTLY.
MILK, EGGS, SUGAR,
CREAM AND FAT.
SASSAFRAS ROOT. THAT
SARSAPARILLA FLAVOR, YOU KNOW?
WOW, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
KIND OF GOOD?
WHEN IT COMES OUT OF
THE MACHINE, I'M GONNA PUT IN
DRIED
SWEET POTATO FLAKES.
PUMP IT UP.
WE MIX THIS
WITH THE PRALINES.
MMM.
THAT'S A REALLY
GOOD FLAVOR. NICE.
SORT OF TASTES LIKE
A SWEET POTATO CASSEROLE
WITH A LITTLE SORT OF ROOT BEER
SORT OF ELEMENT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S ONE OF THOSE FLAVORS
I BREAK OUT FOUR TIMES A YEAR,
BUT WHEN I DO,
IT GOES REALLY FAST.
(man) THERE'S ALWAYS
A DIFFERENT FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT LOOK GOING
TO A NORMAL ICE CREAM SHOP.
THIS IS SPANISH GRAPEFRUIT
ICE CREAM.
AND WHY
DO YOU CALL IT SPANISH?
BECAUSE IT'S FLAVORED
WITH SAFFRON,
SPANISH PAPRIKA AND A LITTLE BIT
OF ALMOND EXTRACT.
WHOA. WOW,
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
IT'S REALLY REFRESHING.
IT'S NOT TOO SWEET.
IT'S NOT TART AND GRAPEFRUIT-Y.
HE'S ALSO MAKING
A FEW THINGS...
WANT A LITTLE BITE?
YOU WON'T
BE FEEDING THE BABY.
THAT GOOD?
BLUEBERRY MOJITO SORBET.
LITTLE BIT OF RUM,
LITTLE BIT OF LIME,
LITTLE BIT OF MINT.
BLUEBERRIES.
THE FIRST THING I'M DOING
IS MAKING A SIMPLE SYRUP,
TEAR UP AND BRUISE UP
THE MINT.
MMM,
THAT SMELLS GREAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
PURéE UP OUR BLUEBERRIES,
AND THEN I'M GONNA REDUCE
THE RUM. WHOLE BOTTLE.
DOWN TO WHAT?
ABOUT HALF.
OH, LOOK AT THAT
RICH COLOR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
JUICE OF FOUR LIMES.
STRAIN IT,
CRUNCH IT, SQUEEZE IT,
DO IT ALL YOURSELF?
NO WONDER YOU'RE HERE
SIX DAYS A WEEK.
A LITER OF BOOZE,
A TON OF SUGAR,
A BUNCH OF BLUEBERRIES.
THERE'S NOT GONNA BE ANYTHING
WRONG WITH THIS.
HAVE AT IT.
MMM.
WHOA.
DEFINITELY GET THE MINT,
DEFINITELY GET THE LIME.
THE PIECES OF BLUEBERRY
ARE GREAT. WELL, THAT'S NICE.
ONLY DO THIS
IN THE SUMMERTIME
WHEN BLUEBERRIES
ARE NICE AND FRESH.
PEOPLE ARE WAITING FOR IT
TO COME AROUND EVERY SUMMER.
WIZARD.
I THINK I TASTE A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT MOJITO IN THERE.
CAN I GET
THE LAVENDER HONEY?
ONE AVOCADOES & CREAM
WITH A SPOON.
I'VE NEVER COME HERE AND HAD
THE SAME THING I'VE HAD BEFORE.
WHAT DO YOU ALL USUALLY GET
WHEN YOU COME HERE?
I JUST DID AN OLD-FASHIONED
ROOT BEER FLOAT.
I GUESS I'M A DRINK-
MY-ICE-CREAM KIND OF GUY.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
IT'S FOUNTAIN TIME...
A MILK SHAKE.
AND A NEW ORLEANS FAVORITE
FOR MORE THAN A CENTURY.
IT'S VERY SWEET.
SWEET POTATO SASSAFRAS.
SAFFRON PISTACHIO,
PLEASE.
UM, THE LAVENDER HONEY.
I'D LIKE
A SKY SCRAPER.
IN THE UPPER GARDEN DISTRICT
OF NEW ORLEANS...
THERE YOU GO.
THE CREOLE CREAMERY
IS SERVING UP
REAL-DEAL ICE CREAM.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE HERE.
IT'S REALLY CREAMY, REALLY GOOD.
AND JUST LIKE NEW ORLEANS...
ONE AVOCADOES & CREAM.
TOTALLY UNIQUE.
SWEET POTATOES GLAZED
WITH ROOT BEER.
NEVER HAD ANYTHING
QUITE LIKE IT.
WE LOVE COMING HERE
'CAUSE IT'S OLD-FASHIONED.
YOU GET THE REALLY TRADITIONAL
ICE CREAM PARLOR DISHES.
LIKE SOMETHING
CALLED NECTAR SODA.
NECTAR IS A MIX
OF ALMOND AND VANILLA
DYED PINK, JUST TO GIVE IT
A PRETTY COLOR.
AS FAR AS I KNOW,
WE'RE THE ONLY PEOPLE
THAT MAKE 'EM IN THE ICE CREAM
SODA FOUNTAIN TRADITIONAL WAY.
SO IT STARTS OUT
WITH SODA MUDDLE,
WHICH IS BASICALLY
JUST SIMPLE SYRUP, MILK
AND VANILLA ICE CREAM.
THIS IS THE NECTAR SYRUP.
RED STUFF.
GIVE IT A LITTLE MIX.
AND THEN WE'LL COME OVER HERE
AND ADD SODA WATER
TO GIVE IT THE CARBONATION. NOW
YOU HAVE A CREAM NECTAR SODA.
DO YOU DRINK THESE OFTEN?
OH, YEAH.
YEAH, THESE ARE GOOD.
AND WE WILL TOP IT OFF WITH
A SCOOP OF VANILLA ICE CREAM,
WHIPPED CREAM
AND A CHERRY.
THERE'S A NECTAR SODA.
WOW. THAT'S--
THAT'S INTERESTING.
IT'S TASTY, YEAH.
YOU'RE ALL EXCITED
ABOUT IT.
YEAH, OH, YEAH.
I LOVE THESE.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT IS?
NECTAR SODA?
YEAH. AND YOU'VE
NEVER HAD ONE?
NOPE.
OH, THERE YOU GO.
OHH!
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S GOOD.
IS THAT GOOD?
YEAH.
IT'S VERY SWEET.
VERY DELICIOUS.
SOMETHING THAT YOU DON'T FIND,
REALLY, ANYMORE,
AND THE GLASS SERVICE IS NICE.
AND IT WAS REALLY GOOD.
HI, MAY I HAVE
A BANANA SPLIT?
THEY'RE DOING
ALL THE CLASSICS--
MALTS, FLOATS AND SHAKES.
AND THIS ONE, THAT COMES
WITH A CAFFEINE KICK.
FROZEN CAPPUCCINO. I'M GONNA PUT
SOME MILK, VANILLA ICE CREAM,
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF SIMPLE SYRUP.
YOU NEED TO PUT
SOME MORE SUGAR IN THERE...
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
EVEN WHEN YOU HAVE
VANILLA ICE CREAM.
HERE'S THE ESPRESSO.
A SCOOP OF CAFé AU LAIT
ICE CREAM. THERE WE GO.
DO I GET WHIPPED CREAM
AND SNACKS?
ABSOLUTELY.
WE'LL PUT SOME ESPRESSO BEANS
ON TOP FOR YOU.
MMM.
OHH. I COULD DRINK THAT.
IT'S NICE AND LIGHT,
BUT YOU GET A REAL GOOD
COFFEE FLAVOR TO IT.
THAT'S A WINNER
RIGHT THERE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
IT'S PERFECT.
EAT ICE CREAM,
BE HAPPY.
(woman)
I LOVE ICE CREAM,
AND THIS IS REALLY
MAKING ME HAPPY.
IT'S GOING OKAY?
YEAH.
YEAH, IT LOOKS LIKE YOU GUYS
ARE DOING PRETTY GOOD--
UNTIL THAT HAPPENED, AND THEN
I PUT SOME OF THOSE ON THERE,
AND THERE YOU GO.
YEAH.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
GELATO.
WOULD YOU LIKE ME
TO MAKE IT?
NO, I KNOW YOU'LL TRY.
PUT A LITTLE MORE ON THERE--
A LITTLE LESS, RATHER.
OH, A LITTLE LESS.
YOU SAID MORE--
LITTLE LESS. YEAH.
A LITTLE MORE, A LITTLE LESS.
ALL DONE.