HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
CHEERS, GUYS.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ROLL IN, HANG OUT,
HAVE A BLAST.
BAR FOOD...
IT'S AWESOME BAR FOOD.
"TRIPLE D" STYLE IN ATLANTA.
WE COME HERE,
AND IT'S JUST COMFORT.
A LATE-NIGHT DIVE BAR...
IT'S A TWISTED CHEERS.
SERVING CURRIED GOAT
TO BACON JERK CHILI...
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE COOKING IT
WITH MEAT DOESN'T MAKE IT JERKY.
NO, NO, NO.
AND WRAPPING THEIR MOZZARELLA
STICKS IN PASTA.
WOW! THAT'S TASTY, MAN.
ORDER OF PIEROGI.
GRANDMA'S COMFORT FOOD...
THAT IS ABOUT SIMPLE
GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
AND A LOUNGE
OUTSIDE PITTSBURG...
YO, MOONDOG.
RUN BY A RETIRED ROCKER...
WHAT'S UP?
WHO PUT DOWN HIS GUITAR
AND PICKED UP A POT.
DO WE REALLY CALL
THIS BAR FOOD?
I DON'T.
AND DOWN IN ALABAMA...
GUMBO. AWESOME.
WHERE BAR FOOD
IS GUMBO BY THE GALLON.
GUY, IF YOU EVER
LOSE YOUR DAY JOB,
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO COME HERE.
AND SATURDAYS MEANS, HEY,
THE CRAWFISH ARE FREE.
IT'S JUST A GOOD EXCUSE
TO GET TOGETHER
WITH FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
WOW, THAT'S HOT. IF I JUST KEEP
EATING, IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, FINDING GREAT BAR FOOD
IS WAY MORE THAN JUST A MENU.
IT'S A WHOLE EXPERIENCE,
LIKE HERE IN ATLANTA
AT THIS JOINT, THE HIGHLANDER.
IT'S A DIVE BAR
IN A STRIP MALL.
NOW THEY'RE HEAVY ON TATTOOS,
BUT SERIOUS
ABOUT SCRATCH COOKING.
(man) CHEERS.
EVERYBODY HERE
IS REALLY TWISTED.
WHO'S GOT THE CHILI
AND FRITTERS?
THE FOOD HERE IS SO MUCH
BETTER THAN IT NEEDS TO BE.
(man) LOOK AT THE MENU--
OXTAIL SOUP.
YOU SEE THAT
ON EVERY DRIVE-THROUGH.
IT'S AWESOME BAR FOOD.
(woman) IT'S VERY FRESH.
WOW. YOU GOT IT GOING ON
WITH THIS, MAN.
IT'S THE NEIGHBORHOOD
PLACE.
HAS BEEN SINCE '92...
YOU WANT
A CIDER, RIGHT?
WHEN JEFF MERBACK AND SOME
BUDDIES TOOK A CHANCE
AND OPENED UP IN A STRIP MALL.
WE STILL, TO THIS DAY,
HAVE FRIENDS COME AND SAY,
"DUDE, THAT WAS THE DUMBEST
IDEA IN THE WORLD,"
AND HERE
WE ARE 16 YEARS LATER.
COLD BEER.
BUT HE REALLY DID
HAVE A PLAN...
THAT'S YOUR BRAND, RIGHT?
LIKE BEING THE PLACE
THAT'S STILL OPEN
AT THE END OF A LONG NIGHT.
FOUR JaGERS--
ABSOLUTELY.
WE KNEW OUR CLIENTELE
WAS GONNA BE BARTENDERS,
WAITERS, WAITRESSES,
COOKS,
AND I COULDN'T THROW OUT
THE TYPICAL BAR FOOD.
STEAMED BROCCOLI.
AND THE DUDE
RUNNING THE KITCHEN
IS THINKING THE SAME WAY.
ALL RIGHT.
TALK TO ME, BUDDY.
JEFF'S LONGTIME BUDDY
FROM WEST AFRICA GOES BY "ICE."
JIBRAHIMA...
OKAY.
GOBBER JAHUMPA.
OH. SO LET'S
JUST GO WITH ICE.
ICE. YEAH.
FRENCH DIP.
HERE YOU GO.
WHEN HE BECAME
OUR KITCHEN MANAGER,
HE BROUGHT HIS PERSONALITY
TO OUR SPECIAL BOARD.
EVERY DAY
SOMETHING'S DIFFERENT.
THEY HAVE
A LOT OF THINGS HERE
THAT A LOT OF PLACES
IN ATLANTA DON'T HAVE.
THIS WEEK OUR SPECIAL
IS OXTAIL SOUP
AND CURRIED GOAT.
YEAH, I'D WALK RIGHT BY HERE
AND GO, "MMM, CURRIED GOAT."
EVEN THEIR CHILI
IS DONE WITH A TWIST.
JERK CHILI?
YEAH.
IT'S THE BEST BOWL
OF CHILI IN TOWN.
WHAT MAKES IT JERK?
THERE'S A JERK MARINADE
THAT WE HAVE FOR IT.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE COOKING IT
WITH MEAT DOESN'T MAKE IT JERK.
NO, NO, NO.
GROUND BEEF.
80/20?
YEAH, AND SPICY
ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
COOK TILL
THEY'RE NICE AND BROWN.
ONIONS--YELLOW, RED--
YELLOW PEPPERS, RED PEPPERS,
GREEN PEPPER.
I LIKE THE COLORS.
NOW WE ADD
THE KIDNEY BEANS,
THE BLACK BEANS
AND A FEW TOMATOES.
NO GARLIC, THOUGH?
THE GARLIC IS COMING
IN THE SECOND PART.
ALL RIGHT,
JUST MAKING SURE.
IT'S ROASTED GARLIC.
THIS LOOKS LIKE ABOUT
THE ENTIRE SPICE COUNTER.
ALMOST.
SO THAT
IS THE... VEGGIE BASE.
THE VEGGIE BASE,
CHICKEN STOCK.
THE HABANEROS.
HABANEROS.
ROASTED GARLIC.
OOH, I LIKE THAT CALL.
YOUR JERK SEASONING.
CAN I TASTE THAT?
NOT TOO SPICY.
SPICED RUM,
TOMATO PASTE.
WE'RE JUST
GONNA MIX
EVERYTHING
THAT'S IN HERE.
NOW HE'S HAPPY NOW,
YOU KNOW?
EVERYBODY MOVE BACK.
THAT'S NICE.
YOU COULD HAVE THAT
IN A HOLSTER.
MAYBE WEAR IT ON A...
(laughs)
PUT THAT IN MY BAG.
THIS GOES IN OUR CAULDRON
OF BEANS AND PEPPERS.
WANT ME TO SCRAPE?
SURE.
I MEAN, IF WE'RE GONNA
BE SAME TEAM.
BROWN SUGAR,
BLACK PEPPER,
THYME, ONION POWDER,
MUSTARD.
DRY MUSTARD, GARLIC POWDER,
BAY LEAF,
MAGGI--KIND OF
LIKE THE SOY
THAT YOU'D GET
ON A CHINESE MENU.
RIGHT. COLOR. CILANTRO?
CILANTRO.
OKAY. RED CHILI FLAKES,
CELERY SEED.
ALLSPICE--
THERE'S YOUR JAMAICAN.
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER.
WHITE PEPPER, CUMIN,
CHILI POWDER.
ROUND IT OUT
WITH THE CAYENNE. WOW.
SO NOW HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET THAT SIMMER FOR?
COUPLE HOURS.
BIG CHUNKS OF MEAT.
STILL SEE ALL THE COLORS.
GOSH, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOT
A LITTLE HEAT TO IT.
GREAT SPICE.
GREAT COLOR.
GREAT TEXTURES.
THAT'S GOOD CHILI.
DUDE, IS THE CHILI LEGIT?
OUTSTANDING.
IT'S MEATY--
LOTS OF NICE SPICE.
CRAZY DEPENDABLE FOOD.
FISH-AND-CHIPS
READY TO ROLL.
THE FISH SPECIALS
ARE ALWAYS AMAZING.
(Guy) REALLY?
THERE'S A WONDERFUL CAPRESE
SALAD THAT I REALLY DIG.
MARINATED LIME CHICKEN.
IT'S GOT A REALLY
REFRESHING LIME MARINADE.
MUSCLES, THE CORN FRITTERS.
WELL, THEY'RE HUGE.
THEY'RE LIKE GOLF-BALL SIZE.
SERVED UP WITH THE HIGHLANDER'S
ROASTED RED PEPPER RéMOULADE.
I LIKE THE RéMOULADE SAUCE
'CAUSE I'M FROM LOUISIANA.
MMM. I LIKE IT, MAN.
I GOT TO MAKE MYSELF A NOTE
ON THAT RéMOULADE.
IT'S SPICY AND DELICIOUS.
AND SERIOUSLY IN DEMAND...
POTATO SKINS ARE UP.
LIKE EVERYTHING HERE...
LITTLE TURKEY SANDWICH
WITH A SALAD.
'CAUSE A LOT OF FOLKS WILL TELL
YOU THIS IS THEIR FIRST CHOICE
FOR EATING OUT...
IT'S GOOD.
AND HANGING OUT.
WHO'S DRY?
GOOD FOOD IS NOTHING
IF YOU DON'T HAVE THE ATMOSPHERE
TO GO ALONG WITH IT.
JaGER? ALL RIGHT.
COMING RIGHT UP.
FROM MOHAWKS
JUST DOWN TO YUPPIES.
IT IS THE EPITOME OF WHERE
YOU'RE ALLOWED TO BE YOURSELF.
EVERYBODY'S WELCOME HERE.
IT'S A TWISTED CHEERS.
ALLY'S ON IT.
PEOPLE WOULD COME HERE
TO DRINK ANYWAY,
AND THEN YOU GET A GREAT MENU
OF FOOD ON TOP OF IT.
EVEN THE BAR BASICS...
NACHOS COMING OUT.
WITH THAT
JAMAICAN JERK CHILI...
TONIGHT I'M EATING
THE LOADED POTATO SKINS.
MINI BURGERS
THEY'RE CALLING SLIDERS...
CHICKEN QUESADILLAS--
I LOVE THEM.
SPICY BUFFALO OR JAMAICAN
JERK CHICKEN WINGS...
BAR FOOD--
YOU DON'T EXPECT MUCH,
BUT HERE THEY GIVE YOU
MADE FROM SCRATCH.
EVEN THE BAR STAPLE
MOZZARELLA STICK--
HERE IT'S WRAPPED IN PASTA.
THEY'RE MUCH BETTER
THAN NORMAL MOZZARELLA STICKS.
IT JUST ADDS A LITTLE
SOMETHING EXTRA TO IT.
I'M GONNA MAKE
AN EGG WASH--
EGG YOLK
AND A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
JUST YOLKS?
I'VE NEVER SEEN IT
DONE THIS WAY.
DONE THIS WAY
UNTIL I CAME HERE.
UNTIL YOU CAME HERE.
THIS IS THE BREADING.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
ITALIAN SEASONING TO IT.
SHEETED EGG PASTA.
BRUSH IT WITH A BIT
OF THE EGG WASH.
JUST LIKE THAT.
THAT'S IT.
JUST ONE ROLLOVER.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DIP IT.
IN WASH AGAIN?
YEAH.
AND THEN IN THE BREADCRUMBS.
I LIKE THIS.
SO NOW
WE'RE GONNA FRY 'EM?
YEAH.
SO DOES THE PASTA GET
CRUNCHY ON THE OUTSIDE?
YEAH.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE WITH THESE?
MARINARA SAUCE.
SCRATCH MADE
WITH ROASTED GARLIC,
ONIONS, PEPPERS, RED WINE,
HERBS AND SPICES.
WOW, THOSE LOOK GOOD!
WOW, I'M IMPRESSED.
THAT'S GREAT, MAN. WOW.
THE SHEET AROUND IT
MAKES IT HOLD TOGETHER,
GIVES IT NICE TEXTURE.
THAT'S TASTY, MAN.
THOSE ARE BANANAS.
THESE ARE DELICIOUS. YEAH.
(Jeff) EVERYONE LOVES HIS FOOD.
HE IS AS GOOD FOR THIS PLACE
AS ANY OF US.
ATLANTA HAS BETTER BAR FOOD
THAN ANY CITY DESERVES.
THE HIGHLANDER'S ONE
OF THE BEST IN TOWN.
YOU COME HERE,
AND IT'S JUST COMFORT.
COMFORT FOOD
IS GREAT FOOD.
WHATEVER THE HOUR...
ROLL IN, HANG OUT,
HAVE A BLAST.
YOU GOT FOOD COMING.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE A BAR,
BUT IT'S NOT BAR FOOD.
SOUTHERN COMFORT FOOD
ALL THE WAY.
YOU STILL LIKE
EACH OTHER?
OH, YEAH.
ANYBODY GOT
A HIGHLANDER TATTOO?
(man) NOT ONE
I CAN SHOW YOU.
UP NEXT...
THANK YOU.
WE'RE HEADING TO A BAR
NEAR PITTSBURGH...
GOOD FRESH FOOD.
WHERE IT'S PIEROGI TIME.
THEY'RE KIND OF
LIKE DUMPLINGS.
1/2 A CUP OF BUTTER?
NO, A 1/2 A POUND.
1/2 A POUND!
WHEN YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A GREAT NEIGHBORHOOD BAR,
WELL, YOU'RE PROBABLY
LOOKING FOR A PLACE
THAT'S BEEN THERE FOR A WHILE.
SO HERE WE ARE IN
BLAWNOX, PENNSYLVANIA,
AT THE STARLITE LOUNGE,
OPENED IN '54,
AND STILL TODAY
A LOCAL FAVORITE.
GOOD PLACE TO HANG OUT,
GRAB A COLD BEER
AND CHECK OUT
SOME HOMEMADE PIEROGIES.
(woman) THEY'RE THE BEST.
(woman) THEY'RE SO GOOD.
MMM.
POLISH DUMPLINGS FILLED,
BOILED AND SAUTéED
IN BUTTER AND ONION.
I THINK THEY'RE FANTASTIC.
THE FOOD IS REALLY GOOD.
GOOD FRESH FOOD.
FROM THE PIEROGIES
TO THE MEAT LOAF,
THE FISH SANDWICH...
HERE WE GO.
CHICKEN DIABLO...
COULDN'T BE BETTER.
AND FETTUCCINI ALFREDO
WITH CHICKEN AND MUSHROOMS.
I DON'T EVEN LIKE MUSHROOMS,
AND I LIKE THIS.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
I GET IT A LOT.
DO WE CALL THIS BAR FOOD?
I DON'T.
UH, NO,
THIS WOULDN'T BE BAR FOOD.
BUT THEY'VE GOT THAT
IF YOU WANT IT.
HOT WINGS, BUFFALO WINGS,
GARLIC AND BUTTERED WINGS.
RONNIE JUST COOKS UP A STORM.
THAT'D BE RON ESSER--
EVERYONE CALLS HIM "MOONDOG,"
A FORMER MUSICIAN
WHO BOUGHT THE STARLITE
ALMOST 14 YEARS AGO.
THE FELLA THAT SOLD IT TO ME
INSISTED THAT IT WOULD ALWAYS--
THAT YOU KEEP THE NAME.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO HE DID,
AND AMPED UP THE MENU...
MMM.
WITH REAL HOME COOKING.
JUST LIKE MAMA LOMBARDI.
OR LORA MAZESKI'S GRANDMA...
I GOT THE RECIPE
FROM MY GRANDMOTHER.
FOR HOMEMADE PIEROGIES,
FOLKS AT THIS JOINT
JUST CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF.
AN AMAZING PLATE OF PIEROGIES.
THEY'RE KIND OF LIKE DUMPLINGS
IN OTHER NATIONALITIES.
POLISH RAVIOLI.
ORDER OF PIEROGI.
AND WHEN IT'S PIEROGI TIME,
LORA LEAVES THE FLOOR
AND HEADS FOR THE KITCHEN.
HOW DO WE START
WITH THE PIEROGI?
YOU NEED
TO MAKE THE DOUGH.
4 CUPS FLOUR,
1 CUP SOUR CREAM,
WATER, TWO EGGS.
STIR IT ALL UP.
AND THIS
IS THE BATTER?
YES.
THEN YOU NEED TO WORK IT
WITH YOUR HANDS.
JUST SUPPOSED TO BE
A STICKY GLOB AT THE BOTTOM?
YEAH. IT'S KIND OF
LIKE DOUGH FOR A PIE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THERE'S
MORE LEFT IN THE BOWL
OR ON YOUR FINGERS.
I'M A MESSY COOK.
PUT IT ASIDE
AND LET IT REST?
FOR 15 TO 20 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE START WORKING
ON THE FILLING?
YEP. AFTER I WASH
MY HANDS, OF COURSE.
JUST GO AHEAD AND WIPE THEM
ON MY SHIRT. I'M JUST KIDDING.
SO WE JUST BOIL DOWN
SOME TATERS?
FOUR TO FIVE.
AND I'M GONNA STICK 'EM
IN MY MIXER.
AMERICAN.
SO WE GOT PROCESSED.
IT HAS TO BE AMERICAN.
IT HAS TO BE AMERICAN?
YES.
SAUTé ONE LARGE ONION.
IN A 1/2 A CUP OF BUTTER?
NO, A 1/2 A POUND.
1/2 A POUND!
YES.
(whistles)
SO WE ARE ALMOST MAKING
THE CONSISTENCY
OF MASHED POTATOES...
YES.
WITH CHEESE
AND A 1/2 POUND OF BUTTER.
YEP.
NOW WE GET THE DOUGH,
AND I FLATTEN IT.
THEN I GRAB FOR THIS
AND FLAP IT OVER
TO MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S SEALED.
CAN I TRY ONE?
OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT, SO I GET
A GLOB OF THIS MIXTURE.
THEN I GET
A LITTLE FLOUR DOWN.
A LITTLE BIT MORE, RIGHT?
YEAH.
THAT LOOKING PRETTY GOOD
AT THIS POINT?
IT LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
IT ALMOST LOOKS
BETTER THAN MINE.
I'M A PIEROGI PRENTICE.
NOW WE GET MOONDOG.
YO, MOONDOG!
NOW WHAT HAPPENS
TO THEM NOW?
WE BOIL THEM
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
NOW WHAT
GETS SERVED WITH THEM?
BUTTER AND ONIONS.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
A LOT OF BUTTER.
WE LET THEM COOK.
I THINK THEY'RE READY.
PRETTY ENORMOUS.
THESE ARE REAL PIEROGIES.
YOU BROWN 'EM.
THEY'RE NICE AND GUSHY...
GUSHY AS A CULINARY TERM.
THERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
WHAT GRANDMA USED TO MAKE.
MMM.
I'M TELLING YOU THAT IS ABOUT
SIMPLE GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
PEOPLE MUST COME DOWN
HERE LOOKING FOR THESE.
THEY'RE GREAT.
GRANDMA WOULD BE HAPPY?
YES.
THERE YOU GOT IT.
WHAT MAKES 'EM SO GOOD?
BUTTER.
(woman) LOTS OF BUTTER--
VERY GOOD.
IT'S A PRETTY POPULAR
PITTSBURGH DISH.
BEST IN THE BURGH.
BEST IN THE BURGH?
THAT'S PITTSBURGH.
IT'S THE BEST PIEROGI
I'VE EVER HAD, ACTUALLY.
JUST A LITTLE PIECE OF A MENU
THAT'S COVERED ALL THE BASES
FOR YEARS.
HE ALWAYS HAS A LOT OF VERY GOOD
DIFFERENT KINDS OF FOOD.
(man) FISH SANDWICH.
SINCE I WAS A KID,
THIS PLACE WAS KNOWN FOR HAVING
A GREAT FISH SANDWICH.
AND RON
MAKES IT EVEN BETTER.
THINGS DON'T HAVE TO BE
THAT FANCY TO BE GOOD.
(woman) OH, THEY HAVE ALL
KINDS OF DIFFERENT STUFF.
IT'S THE BEST FOOD AROUND HERE.
(woman) ESPECIALLY THE SOUP--
STUFFED PEPPER SOUP.
IT TASTES LIKE HOMEMADE.
'CAUSE IT IS.
SO THE INGREDIENTS
OF STUFFED PEPPERS,
BUT INSTEAD, YOU CHOP IT ALL
UP AND MAKE SOUP OUT TO IT.
BASICALLY.
WE LIKE
TO MAKE IT FRESH.
NOW WHO CAME UP
WITH THE RECIPE?
IT ORIGINATED IN 1860--
NO, I DON'T KNOW.
REAL NICE TOMATO BASE
TO IT.
ON A COLD PITTSBURGH DAY,
THIS WOULD BE WHAT
YOU'D WANT TO GO FOR.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S REAL TASTY.
ONE ORDER FOR YOU.
THIS IS LIKE
A SIT-DOWN RESTAURANT.
THERE'S A FULL MENU.
IF YOU'RE IN THE MOOD
FOR A BURGER, WINGS--
THEY HAVE PASTA.
AND IF ALL
YOU WANT'S A SALAD...
SO YOU GOT MELTED CHEESE
AND FRENCH FRIES
ON TOP OF A COLD SALAD.
THIS IS THE BEST
CHICKEN SALAD
YOU EVER HAD
IN YOUR WHOLE LIFE,
AND THE FRENCH FRIES
ARE SO GOOD.
HAND-CUT AND DOUBLE FRIED.
THE SAME SCRATCH COOKING
THAT'S KEPT THE LOCALS
PILING IN FOREVER.
SEE, I WAS BORN
AND RAISED IN THIS TOWN,
SO I'VE PROBABLY BEEN
COMING HERE 50 YEARS.
(man) PEOPLE KEEP
COMING BACK
BECAUSE IT HAS
A HOME ATMOSPHERE.
PRETTY MUCH KNOW
EVERYBODY THAT'S HERE.
AND YOU KNOW YOU CAN
COUNT ON GOOD FOOD.
IF YOU'RE GONNA COOK, YOU
MIGHT AS WELL DO IT, RIGHT?
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
(man) CHICKEN DIABLO.
IT'S QUALITY STUFF.
WHO MADE THE RECIPE?
THE DEVIL, I GUESS.
I DON'T KNOW.
I MADE IT.
THIS IS THE CAST
OF CHARACTERS?
PEPPERS, SOME ONIONS.
GET THE CHICKEN GOING.
I GROW THESE PEPPERS,
AND THEN I CAN 'EM.
YELLOW PEPPERS?
YELLOW.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF MARINARA ON IT.
SRIRACHA.
DO YOU WANT SOME
OF THAT IN YOURS?
YOU CAN PUT A LITTLE
TASTE OF IT IN THERE.
JUST CUT IT UP
A LITTLE BIT, THE CHICKEN.
CUT IT RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
THROW IT IN.
THROW A LITTLE PASTA
IN THERE. MMM.
WOW, THAT'S A PORTION, HUH?
THAT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WHAT? A LITTLE
PARMESAN CHEESE ON TOP?
MMM.
THE PEPPER AND THE CHICKEN
AND THE SPICE
REALLY GO TOGETHER GREAT.
THOSE PEPPERS
ARE DYNAMITE, MAN.
ALL I WANT TO DO IS FIND
MORE OF THOSE PEPPERS.
SPICY--ABSOLUTELY GREAT.
ALFREDO.
(woman) THERE'S NOT
TOO MANY PLACES
THAT YOU WOULD GO,
EVEN IN PITTSBURGH,
WHERE YOU WOULD FIND
THESE KIND OF PASTA DISHES,
AND THEN YOU ALSO FIND
WINGS AND BURGERS
AND BAR FOOD.
THANK YOU.
AND GRANDMA'S PIEROGIES.
HOMEMADE PIEROGIES--
VERY GOOD.
THEY'RE GREAT.
I'LL TELL YOU
THIS, MOONDOG,
IT'S NOT WHAT
I WOULD EXPECT
TO FIND AT A LOUNGE.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
BIG GUY,
BIG PORTIONS.
HOW TALL ARE YOU?
I'M 6'10".
THERE'S NOT MUCH
OF THIS RIGHT NOW
THAT I'M ENJOYING.
NEXT UP...
(man) CUP OF SHRIMP.
WE'RE HEADING SOUTH...
I'M HAVING THE GUMBO,
OF COURSE.
AND THE BEER'S
ALWAYS COLD HERE, TOO.
FOR BAR FOOD ALABAMA STYLE.
THE ABSOLUTE BEST GUMBO
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
WE'RE
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
BUT ONCE IN A WHILE,
ON A VERY SPECIAL OCCASION,
WE'LL INVITE A SHACK
INTO THE FAMILY,
ESPECIALLY IF THE SHACK
IS A DOWN-HOME BAR
CALLED THE GUMBO SHACK,
GIVING AWAY FREE CRAWFISH
HERE IN FAIRHOPE, ALABAMA.
NOW THIS GUY HAS GOT TO SEE
A GUY NAMED GUY.
ORDER UP.
GUY AND TERRA, THE OWNERS,
ARE JUST THE BEST PEOPLE
TO BE AROUND.
THE OYSTERS.
GUMBO.
(man) WONDERFUL.
CUP OF SHRIMP.
THE ABSOLUTE BEST GUMBO
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
THIS IS
THE BEST GUMBO.
THIS IS THE BEST GUMBO?
IT'S SO SPICY.
SPICY.
I'M FROM LOUISIANA,
AND THIS IS AS CLOSE
AS I'M GONNA GET
TO LOUISIANA COOKING.
IT'S ALL MADE BY A SELF-TAUGHT
FORMER HIGH SCHOOL PRINCIPAL...
WE HAD A RESTAURANT IN ATLANTA.
WE HAD A BARBECUE RESTAURANT.
UNTIL GUY AND TERRA BERRY
WENT LOOKING FOR A LIFE
CLOSER TO THE BEACH.
WE'RE JUST--YEAH.
JUST TIRED OF ATLANTA.
AND THEY FOUND IT
ALMOST SIX YEARS AGO
WHEN THEY BOUGHT THIS JOINT
IN FAIRHOPE.
IT'S A LOT OF FOLKS'
FAVORITE BAR...
♪ ALABAMA ♪
BUT THE BIGGEST ATTRACTION?
IS THAT THE PRIMARY
ITEM HERE IS GUMBO?
(laughs)
YEAH.
GUMBO. AWESOME.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
THIS FROM?
I CAME UP WITH THIS MYSELF.
THIS IS MY OWN RECIPE.
REALLY?
SO THIS IS A LITTLE--
TRIAL AND ERROR.
ALL RIGHT, START OUT
WITH 4 POUNDS OF BUTTER,
DICED BELL PEPPERS...
THAT'S A LOT
OF BELL PEPPERS.
10 POUNDS OF CELERY,
GARLIC.
WHAT'S THAT?
ABOUT 2 POUNDS?
4 POUNDS.
4 POUNDS OF GARLIC?
REALLY?
BLACK PEPPER,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
SEAFOOD SEASONING,
BASIL,
HANDFUL OF BAY LEAVES,
THYME...
AND THEN--
ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE'S NOT EVEN ANY WATER
IN THIS THING,
AND IT'S ABOUT HALFWAY FULL.
BONELESS CHICKEN THIGHS,
CHICKEN STOCK.
SO WE'LL MAKE A ROUX OUT OF FAT
AND JUICES THAT COME FROM THIS.
YES, SIR.
'CAUSE YOU HAVE TO HAVE FAT IN
THE FLOUR--SOME KIND OF FAT.
AND THE BUTTER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE'S A LOT OF STIRRING.
A LOT OF STIRRING.
THAT'S WHAT WE DO HERE.
IT'S ALREADY STARTING
TO SMELL GOOD.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO NOW
IS BEGIN
THE MOST IMPORTANT PART,
WHICH IS MAKING THE ROUX.
MMM. OH.
SEE, I'D LIKE TO SCOOP THAT
OUT AND PUT IT IN A SANDWICH.
ADD THE FLOUR.
OH, YOU'RE SERIOUS
ABOUT THIS.
THAT'S IT, MAN.
MAKE SURE THAT GETS
MIXED IN GOOD
'CAUSE WE DON'T WANT
ANY LUMPS IN THE ROUX.
WE ADD THE WATER
ALL THROUGH THIS PROCESS.
WE DON'T PUT IT
ALL IN AT ONE TIME.
WE JUST KEEP STIRRING
AND KEEP ADDING WATER.
NOW YOU'RE MAKING GUMBO.
GUY, IF YOU EVER LOSE YOUR
DAY JOB ON THE FOOD CHANNEL,
YOU'RE WELCOME
TO COME HERE.
(laughs)
NOW WE'LL JUST LET
THAT ROUX COOK
FOR ABOUT, I'D SAY THREE HOURS
OR SO, AND YOU'RE THERE.
AFTER THE ROUX'S
FINISHED,
WHICH YOU CAN SEE
IT IS NOW,
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
TOMATO CONCENTRATE.
DICED TOMATOES AND THE OKRA.
AND WE MIX THIS ALL UP?
THAT'S CORRECT, AND WE BRING
YOU BACK UP TO TEMPERATURE.
BRING IT BACK UP TO TEMPERATURE,
AND WHEN THAT'S DONE...
IT'S DONE.
THERE YOU GO.
TO GUY FROM GUY.
MMM.
WOW.
THAT IS RICH.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE
COMING IN.
YEAH, I'M STARTING
TO PICK IT UP.
GOOD COOK DOWN
ON THE ANDOUILLE.
I LIKE WHEN IT GETS A NICE
FIRM TEXTURE TO IT.
UNIQUE GUMBO, BUDDY.
WELL DONE.
GOOD JOB, GUY, GUY.
THAT'S IT, BROTHER.
GUY.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
EXACTLY THE WAY
I LIKE IT.
YOU CAN HAVE SHRIMP,
OYSTERS, CRAWFISH--
WHATEVER YOU WANT
TO ADD TO IT.
IF I DON'T GET BACK
TO LOUISIANA THAT OFTEN,
I COME OVER HERE
AND GET THE GUMBO.
LIKE WE SAY OVER THERE,
"çA C'EST BON,"
WHICH MEANS VERY, VERY GOOD.
AND HE'S DOING THE WHOLE CAJUN
AND CREOLE THING THE SAME WAY--
RED BEANS AND RICE,
JAMBALAYA--
BUT HE NEVER DID
GIVE UP THAT BARBECUE.
HE'S TAKEN ON
THE GUMBO REAL GOOD,
BUT HIS BARBECUE IS EXCELLENT.
WHERE WE AT?
WE ON PORK SANDWICHES?
HE BROUGHT THE RECIPES
AND SMOKER WITH HIM
ALL THE WAY FROM ATLANTA.
IT'S AN INTERESTING DESIGN.
YOU DON'T SEE
THIS MUCH, GUY,
WHEN IT COMES
TO BIG COOKERS.
SMOKE COMES UP, IT COMES
UNDERNEATH THE MEAT,
TURNS DOWN HERE
AND COMES BACK ACROSS
THE TOP OF THE MEAT
AND OUT.
IT'S CALLED
A CONVECTION PROCESS.
HE'S DOING PORK BUTTS
AND TURKEY BREASTS.
LOOK HOW THAT CAME OUT.
IT LOOKS GREAT.
BEST TURKEY. TRY IT.
THAT IS KILLER.
BUT WHAT'S BECOME
A LOCAL FAVORITE?
TURKEY, LETTUCE
AND TOMATO.
T.L.T. IS WHAT
YOU NORMALLY HAVE?
USUALLY, YEAH.
AND IT IS AWESOME.
WITH THE ALABAMA SAUCE--
YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
NOW IS THIS SOMETHING
YOU REALLY FIND
WHEN YOU COME TO ALABAMA,
OR IS THIS WHAT YOU CALL?
NO, THIS ACTUALLY ORIGINATED
FROM HUNTSVILLE, ALABAMA.
MAYONNAISE, CIDER VINEGAR,
BLACK PEPPER.
AND THAT'S IT
FOR ALABAMA SAUCE?
THAT'S ALABAMA SAUCE.
PERFECT.
YOU'RE SERIOUS ABOUT THAT.
THERE YOU GO.
A T.L.T.--
TURKEY, LETTUCE AND TOMATO.
SO THAT'S LIKE
A ZESTY MAYO.
THAT TURKEY SMOKE
SPEAKS WELL.
I GOT TO WRITE
THAT ONE DOWN.
VERY SIMPLE.
IT'S GOOD.
LOVE
THE ALABAMA SAUCE.
DEFINITELY KICKS UP
A SANDWICH A LOT.
FOOD IS FABULOUS, AND IT'S JUST
A FUN PLACE TO COME.
(man) COME ON!
HOW OFTEN
DO YOU COME HERE?
ABOUT THREE DAYS
A WEEK.
THREE DAYS A WEEK?
THREE DAYS OR NIGHTS?
UH, NIGHTS.
WE LOVE IT.
WE COME HERE EVERY SUNDAY.
BUT DON'T FORGET SATURDAY.
IN CRAWFISH SEASON,
THAT'S GIVEAWAY DAY.
FREE CRAWFISH?
IT'S JUST A CUSTOM.
IT'S JUST A GOOD EXCUSE
TO GET TOGETHER
WITH FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
WOW, THAT'S HOT. IF I JUST KEEP
EATING, IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
♪ I'M GOING TO ALABAMA ♪
THE GUMBO SHACK
IN FAIRHOPE, ALABAMA,
IS A FAVORITE LOCAL BAR...
CUP OF SHRIMP.
WHERE EVERYTHING'S COOKING.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOVE THE FOOD,
LOVE THE SPICES.
I'M HAVING THE GUMBO, OF COURSE.
AND THE BEER'S
ALWAYS COLD HERE, TOO.
EVERY SATURDAY
IN CRAWFISH SEASON,
THEY'RE GIVING 'EM AWAY--
REALLY.
CRAWFISH HAS BEEN
AROUND THIS AREA FOREVER...
THANK YOU.
BUT GUY'S IS THE BEST
AROUND HERE.
WHEN GUMBO SHACK OWNER
GUY BERRY
LEFT ATLANTA
AND TOOK OVER THIS JOINT,
HE BROUGHT IN LYLE WESTON,
A LOCAL CRAWFISH DUDE
WITH HIS OWN STYLE
OF SPICING THINGS UP.
THEY DON'T CHANGE OUT THE BOIL.
THE HEAT GETS STRONGER
AND GETS STRONGER,
AND YOU JUST CAN'T STAND IT.
THIS RIGHT HERE IS WHAT
WE CALL CRAB BOIL.
IT'S GOT LIKE PAPRIKA
AND CAYENNE...
ALL THE GOOD STUFF.
AND FENNEL,
AND THERE'S JUST A WHOLE--
GET SOME CORIANDER,
AND EVERYBODY'S IN THERE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT--
WELL, A LOT OF BIT OF SALT.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT
THEY OPEN THAT WAY.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
THROW IN POUND OF BUTTER.
THIS HAS GOT MUSTARD SEED,
BASIL, BAY LEAVES.
YOU LOOK INSIDE OF THERE--
THAT'S GOT--
THAT'S GOT
ALL THE GOOD STUFF.
CREOLE SEASONING, WHITE
PEPPER, BLACK PEPPER,
CAYENNE.
CAN PEOPLE FEEL
THEIR TONGUES AFTER THEY EAT?
OH, WELL, YOUR LIPS WILL
BURN FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME BEER.
TO SMOOTH OUT
SOME OF THAT SPICE,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE CITRUS.
REALLY?
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC
TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE FLAVOR.
STILL NO CRAWFISH.
FIRST, HE'S DOING SOME VEGGIES
AND SOME ALABAMA SAUSAGE.
WOW.
FINALLY,
WHEN THEY'RE DONE...
LOOK AT THAT
BOUNTIFUL FEAST.
IT'S TIME TO RELOAD
FOR THE MAIN EVENT.
SALT HELPS...
YEAH?
A LOT IN THE ACTUAL
SEASONING OF THE CRAWFISH,
AND IT BREAKS DOWN
THE SHELL
TO WHERE IT'S NOT QUITE
AS TOUGH TO OPEN.
NOW WE MOVE ON
TO THE CRAWFISH.
DO YOU SAY ANYTHING
TO THEM?
WELL, SEE YOU
IN A LITTLE WHILE.
THESE ARE ONLY GONNA GO
FOR ABOUT FIVE, SIX MINUTES,
AND THEY'LL FLOAT.
WHOA.
I ADD THIS ICE
TO KIND OF SHOCK 'EM,
AND THE LONGER I LET 'EM
SIT AND SOAK,
THE MORE SPICY
THEY'LL BECOME.
YOU JUST GRAB 'EM...
RIGHT.
GONNA PINCH THE HEAD
A LITTLE BIT...
YEAH.
GET ALL THE SPICE
OUT OF IT...
MM-HMM.
AND PITCH THAT
TO THE SIDE.
PULL OF THAT
FIRST SEGMENT...
'CAUSE THAT
RELEASES IT.
SQUEEZE THE BOTTOM
AND PULL IT OUT
OF THE SHELL.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
NICE SPICE.
REALLY TENDER.
WOW, THAT'S HOT.
(laughs)
IF I JUST KEEP EATING,
IT'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
THE CRAWFISH IS FANTASTIC.
YOU CAN FIND CRAYFISH ANYWHERE,
BUT THESE ARE REALLY GOOD.
MY LIPS ARE ON FIRE!
ON THE HOUSE,
MY FRIEND.
YOU GOTTA COUNT
ON A GUY NAMED GUY
TO BRING YOU
A COLD ONE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY--
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
IN AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
LION HEAD?
OH, YEAH.
BECAUSE YOU CAN
DO THE VOICE.
THE LION ON
"THE WIZARD OF OZ."
(imitates
Cowardly Lion laugh)
(laughter)
HE WOWS THE CROWD.