HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
CAN'T STOP COMIN'.
IT'S THE BEST FOOD.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
JUST LIKE MOM'S
GOOD COOKIN'.
WOW.
COOKIN' IT OLD-SCHOOL...
YUM-YUM.
IN PITTSBURGH...
TWO REUBENS.
HOME-STYLE
ROAST BEEF SANDWICHES.
A LITTLE BAR...
AND I NEED
THE HOT SAUCE, HONEY.
WHERE ONE FAMILY'S DISHIN' UP
WHAT THEY'VE ALWAYS LOVED.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE FOOD.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
GREAT STUFF.
HERE Y'ALL GO.
IN NEW ORLEANS...
I LOVE THE RAW OYSTERS.
NEARLY 90 YEARS...
THEY'RE THE BEST.
AND STILL GOIN' STRONG.
IT'S LIKE A TRADITION.
AND A SEAFOOD LEGEND
IN A SEAFOOD TOWN.
(moans)
AND IN OMAHA...
FRIED CHICKEN UP.
SWEET POTATO PUDDING.
BIG PLATES
OF OLD-SCHOOL SOUL FOOD.
IT'S HOW CHICKEN
USED TO BE.
AND AT THIS JOINT...
WHOO.
THEY'RE DOIN' IT ALL.
FRIED OKRA. PIG EARS.
YOU'VE NEVER HAD
A PIG EAR?
ALL RIGHT.
EAT IT!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
HERE ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF PITTSBURGH,
THINGS HAVE BEEN AROUND
FOR A WHILE.
YOU'VE GOT HUNDRED-YEAR-OLD
HOUSES AND PLACES LIKE THIS.
IT'D BEEN A NEIGHBORHOOD
BAR FOR DECADES.
NOW IT'S CALLED NADINE'S,
AND IT'S BECOME A LOCAL FAVORITE
FOR SOMETHING ELSE--
REAL HOME COOKIN'.
IT TASTES JUST LIKE
MOM'S GOOD COOKIN'.
TWO REUBENS.
HOME-STYLE ROAST
BEEF SANDWICHES.
MMM, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE FOODS.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
WELL, IF IT'S A BIGGER GUY,
I GIVE HIM MORE.
YOU SIZE UP
THE PERSON HERE?
AND THEY CAN
HAVE SECONDS
IF THEY WANT IT.
NUH-UNH.
EVERYBODY HAS FAST FOOD, AND I
WANTED SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
SO NADINE VOELKER BOUGHT
A NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
HOW ARE YOU GUYS
DOIN' TODAY?
AND AMPED IT UP WITH COOKIN'
SHE WAS DOIN' AT HOME.
DO YOU MEASURE AT HOME?
NO, I DON'T.
IT'S JUST HOME COOKING.
FROM HER HOME CREW.
(Nadine) MY SON MATTHEW,
MY DAUGHTER MARISSA.
MY HUSBAND WORKS AT NIGHT.
WELL, IF I'M BUSY, THE CUSTOMERS
WILL COME AND HELP.
OH?
EVERY DAY, SHE HAS
DIFFERENT SPECIALS.
THURSDAY WE'RE GONNA DO
SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALLS.
(man) AND YOU CAN COME HERE
THREE DIFFERENT TIMES,
HAVE THREE DIFFERENT SPECIALS,
AND IT'S ALL GOOD.
FRIDAY WE'RE GONNA
RUN THE ROAST BEEF.
HOW IS IT?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA ROAST
OUR OWN BEEF NOW?
IN AN OVEN THAT'S
THIS BIG.
YES. WITH A BROKEN DOOR.
WITH A BROKEN DOOR.
IT'S A NADINE ORIGINAL.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I'M GONNA PUT
SOME GARLIC IN IT.
WHO TAUGHT YOU THIS?
FOOD NET.
"GUY'S BIG BITE"?
YEP.
NOW WHAT? SOME, UH--
MONTREAL STEAK SEASONING,
SALT AND PEPPER.
I DON'T HAVE A RACK
THAT FITS THAT,
SO I MAKE MY OWN RACK.
BY PUTTIN' THE CELERY
AND ONION ON THE BOTTOM.
YES.
AND THEN WILL YOU USE THAT
TO MAKE YOUR AU JUS?
I USE THAT
TO MAKE MY GRAVY, YES.
NOW WE ROAST IT?
I HAVE TO SEAR IT FIRST.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
IN THE OVEN NEXT.
I GOT IT.
AAH!
JUST KIDDIN'.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME WATER NOW
SO IT DOESN'T BURN.
NO TIMING.
I JUST GUESS.
NADINE, WE'RE, LIKE,
ON OUR LAST THREAD.
NOTHIN' WRONG WITH THIS.
THANK YOU.
AND YOU LET THAT REST FOR,
LIKE, WHAT, A HALF-HOUR?
YES.
HERE, LET ME GET THAT PIECE
OUT OF THE WAY.
I DON'T WANT THAT
TO CLOG ANYTHING.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
THAT'S ALMOST ILLEGAL.
NOW WHAT'S THIS GONNA
GET SERVED WITH?
RED SKIN MASHED POTATOES.
AND YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
A GRAVY OUT OF--
I'M GONNA MAKE IT
OUT OF THIS STOCK.
SO WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A LITTLE ROUX.
HOW MUCH FLOUR DO YOU
WANT DOWN? ONE MORE?
ONE MORE.
GONNA ADD MY DEMI-GLACE.
YOU REALLY BUY
DEMI-GLACE?
YES, I DO.
I LOVE THIS.
DEMI-GLACE IS WHAT REALLY ADDS
THAT DEEP, RICH FLAVOR
TO IT ALL.
RIGHT. I'M GONNA ADD
THE BEEF STOCK.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOKS GOOD,
DOESN'T IT?
OH, IT SMELLS GREAT.
JUST WHAT I EXPECTED
WHEN I DROVE UP TO THIS
LITTLE HOLE-IN-THE-WALL.
DIDN'T YOU?
GONNA ADD THE ROAST
BEEF TO THIS.
I LIKE TO SMOTHER IT
IN THE GRAVY.
IF YOU'RE GONNA
GET SMOTHERED,
THAT'S SOMETHING
TO GET SMOTHERED IN.
OH... MMM-MMM.
THAT'S IT.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM, THE MEAT'S GREAT.
NICE AND TENDER.
I WOULD EAT, LIKE, AN OLD
ARMY BOOT WITH THAT GRAVY.
THAT'S ON LIKE "DONKEY KONG"
RIGHT THERE.
JUMP OVER THE BARREL,
GET THE HAMMER
AND SAVE THE GIRL.
SERIOUSLY, I COULD DO
THE WHOLE PLATE.
TASTES GREAT. THIS IS
THE KIND OF STUFF THAT I LOVE.
GREAT FOOD
AT A GREAT PRICE.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS $4.50.
NO!
AS MY SPECIALS, YES.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THE SANDWICH IS ONLY $4.50.
BUT THE NAPKINS
ARE 800 BUCKS.
IT'S MY SECOND BOWL.
NO!
I COULD HAVE MORE?
ABSOLUTELY.
I GIVE SECONDS FREE.
IT REMINDS ME OF HOME.
IT'S HOT. WATCH HOW
YOU BITE INTO IT.
A LOT OF THEM SAY
I'M THEIR SECOND MOTHER.
LITTLE THINNER
ON THAT, MATT.
RUNNING A FAMILY
DINING ROOM
FOR THE ENTIRE NEIGHBORHOOD.
(Nadine) HOW WAS
YOUR DAY TODAY?
VERY GOOD. THANK YOU.
WE HAVE EVERY
CUSTOMER'S NAME,
AND WHEN IT'S THEIR BIRTHDAY,
I PUT THEIR NAME UP.
"BOB, DONALD, BO...
SASA"?
THAT IS MY
MARCH MADNESS CREW.
(whistles)
HERE YOU GO, TONYA.
THANK YOU.
SHE KNOWS HER CROWD
AND WHAT THEY LOVE...
IT'S MY FAVORITE
SANDWICH HERE.
REALLY?
FROM REUBENS
TO MONSTER MEATBALLS...
THEY'RE LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
YOU CAN'T GET 'EM
ANYWHERE ELSE.
OH, MAN,
LOOK AT THAT.
CAN YOU SEE ME?
GREAT STUFF.
TO NADINE'S OWN TAKE
ON A CHILDHOOD FAVORITE.
FRIED BOLOGNA SANDWICH.
IT'S ALSO KNOWN AS A FRIED
JUMBO SANDWICH AROUND HERE.
JUMBO?
JUMBO.
LET ME CHECK THAT JUST
FOR QUALITY'S SAKE.
FRESHLY SLICED, TOO.
AND THEN WE'LL THROW IT
ALL OVER THE GRILL HERE.
SOME FRESH-CUT ONIONS, COUPLE
OF FRESH-CUT GREEN PEPPERS.
I LIKE TO THROW IN
A LOT OF JALAPEÑOS.
YOU LIKE HOT STUFF, RIGHT?
I SURE DO.
RIGHT ON TOP?
OH, RIGHT ON TOP.
TAKE A COUPLE PIECES OF CHEESE.
WE'LL JUST LAY IT
RIGHT ON HERE.
WE'RE GONNA NEED
A COUPLE OF ICE CUBES.
SHOW 'EM
A LITTLE SQUEEZE IN.
WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT STEAM
GETS SUPERHOT--
JUST NAILS THAT CHEESE.
AHH.
TOASTED BREAD AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT SPICY DELI MUSTARD.
NOW THAT'S
A BOLOGNA SANDWICH.
YOU'RE TELLIN' ME.
DUDE, THAT IS LEGIT.
WHAT A GREAT SANDWICH.
THAT'S CARAMELIZED CARNAGE
OF GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S IT.
AMAZING BOLOGNA SANDWICHES.
(woman) FRIED BOLOGNA IS
SOMETHING MY MOM ALWAYS MADE
FOR MY DAD WHEN
I WAS A KID.
AND NADINE'S KIDS...
PATRICK, YOU READY
FOR ONE THERE, BUDDY?
THEY GREW UP ON THIS.
NAY'S PASTA.
THIS IS, LIKE,
THE SIGNATURE ITEM HERE
OF NADINE'S?
BOTH OF MY SONS
ARE FOOTBALL PLAYERS.
THAT'S WHO YOU WERE
MAKING THIS FOR.
FOR HIM AND ALL
THE FOOTBALL TEAM, CORRECT.
JUST REALLY GOOD.
SPICY, BUT NOT TOO SPICY.
(Nadine) THIS IS HOT SAUSAGE.
I BREAK IT UP ON HERE.
DO YOU COOK ALL THIS UP?
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME CUT-UP SALAMI,
CUT-UP CAPICOLA.
NOW THIS RIGHT HERE--
LET ME--I DON'T--
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
MMM, THAT'S HOT ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
I DIDN'T--
AND THIS IS ROASTED
ONIONS AND PEPPERS.
SO FAR, WHATEVER
WE'RE MAKIN' IS GREAT.
TOMATOES?
DICED TOMATOES.
WE GOT THE WHOLE BOUNTY
ON THAT ONE--
THE SHELLS, WE GOT
THE PENNE RIGATE,
SOME FUSILLI.
A LITTLE BIT OF ASIAGO CHEESE,
AND MIX IT ALL UP.
I ALWAYS ENJOY MY PASTA
WHEN THE MEAT-TO-PASTA
RATIO IS 50/50.
THIS IS JUST STRAIGHT-UP
TOMATO SAUCE.
WHOA!
THAT'S ENOUGH.
THEN I PUT IT IN THE OVEN
AND I BAKE IT.
YEAH, YOU CAN PUT
A LID ON IT.
AND ONE, TWO,
THREE, FOUR.
MUST BE AN IMPORTANT DISH.
FOUR WRAPS.
(whistles)
MMM.
NOW A LITTLE ASIAGO?
A LITTLE ASIAGO.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU HAD ME AT "HELLO."
OH, MY GOD.
GREAT SAUSAGE.
THE SALAMI--NICE AND SALTY.
THE CAPICOLA GIVES
A NICE SWEETNESS TO IT.
EXCELLENT. REALLY NICE.
WINNER, WINNER,
ITALIAN DINNER.
THIS PASTA IS GREAT.
PASTA DISH RIGHT THERE--
THAT'S BANANAS.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
I CAN'T STOP COMIN'.
IT'S THE BEST FOOD.
IT'S LIKE HOME--
HOMEMADE FOOD.
STUFF THAT, YOU KNOW,
MOM USED TO MAKE.
THANK YOU.
DON'T LET ME
INTERRUPT YOU.
(woman) HE'S NOT GONNA TALK.
HE'S EATING.
MY STRING BROKE!
NEWS AT 11:00.
WE'RE HERE AT NADINE'S
AND, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE STRING OF YEARS
HAS BROKEN JUST WHEN
WE HAPPENED TO BE HERE.
NADINE, HOW DO
YOU FEEL ABOUT IT?
TERRIBLE.
UP NEXT...
YOU'RE JUST GONNA SPLIT 'EM?
WE'RE HEADIN' SOUTH
TO NEW ORLEANS...
COME HERE FOR THE BASS.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOIN'
THE FRESHEST SEAFOOD...
IT'S HISTORIC.
FOR NEARLY 90 YEARS.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
HERE IN NEW ORLEANS,
EVERYBODY KNOWS MAGAZINE STREET.
IT'S FULL OF HISTORY
AND RESTAURANTS,
AND YOU'LL FIND SOME
OF THE BEST OF BOTH
AT HIS LOCAL LANDMARK,
CASAMENTO'S, WHERE THEY'VE BEEN
DOIN' IT OLD-SCHOOL
FOR CLOSE TO 90 YEARS.
HERE Y'ALL GO.
IS THIS
THE APPETIZER BAR?
JUST STARTIN'
ON MY FIRST DOZEN.
I LOVE
THE RAW OYSTERS HERE.
IT'S LIKE A TRADITION.
IT'S HISTORIC.
YOU JUST GONNA
SPLIT 'EM?
MMM.
COME HERE
FOR THE BASS.
PLACE IS JUST BUSTIN' OUT
OF THE SEAMS HERE.
AND IT'S BEEN THAT WAY
SINCE 1919,
WHEN ORIGINAL OWNER
JOE CASAMENTO
SHUCKED HIS FIRST OYSTER HERE.
AND THIS IS THE WAY
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN?
THE WAY IT'S
ALWAYS BEEN.
AND THIRD GENERATION OWNER
C.J. GERDES
IS STILL SHUCKIN' 'EM
LIKE GRANDPA DID.
CUSTOMERS COME IN HERE.
AS SOON AS THEY SEE
GUYS SHUCKIN', THEY'LL LOOK
OVER THE COUNTER AND SAY,
"HOW THEY LOOKIN' TODAY?"
(Guy) DO YOU LIKE THE BIG ONES
OR THE LITTLE ONES?
AT CASAMENTO'S,
THEY ALL TASTE GOOD.
IS THERE A SHUCKER NUMBER ONE
AND A SHUCKER NUMBER TWO?
HE'S NUMBER ONE.
BEST IN THE STATE.
5-TIME CHAMP?
THAT'D BE MIKE ROGERS.
NUMBER ONE SHUCKER.
RIGHT THERE. GO.
OKAY, THAT WAS THE FIRST ONE
IN SIX SECONDS.
2 IN 12 SECONDS.
THAT'S 6 IN 34 SECONDS.
THAT'S EIGHT,
AND THIS'LL ROUND OUT TEN
IN A MINUTE AND
FIVE SECONDS,
AND YOU NEED MORE PEOPLE?
YOU PUT IT UP AGAINST
THIS THING?
OKAY, SO YOU'RE HOLDING
IT OPEN LIKE THAT,
AND THEN JUST GIVE IT
A LITTLE FLICK OVER.
DO IT WITH YOUR THUMB.
LET YOUR THUMB
DO THE WORK.
OKAY, THERE WE GO.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW IT DOESN'T LOOK
LIKE A FROG IN A BLENDER.
YOU DID GOOD.
ALWAYS START OFF
WITH RAW OYSTERS.
THEY'RE THE BEST.
JUST A PLATE AND A SETUP.
THIS IS CALLED
THE SETUP?
MM-HMM.
(whistles) ELABORATE.
ALL THE CONDIMENTS
AND EVERYTHING
ARE ALL ON
THE TABLE ALREADY.
THEY JUST GIVE YOU
ALL THE INGREDIENTS,
AND YOU MIX IT.
EVERYTHING FROM HORSERADISH
TO HOT SAUCE.
MINE'S HALF HORSERADISH
AND HALF KETCHUP.
A WHOLE LOTTA LEMON.
I PUT KETCHUP, HOT SAUCE
AND HORSERADISH.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
AND THEN JUST--
DOWN IT GOES.
WOW, THAT'S NICE
AND SMOOTH.
THAT'S AN OYSTER
SANDWICH THERE.
IT'S JUST SUCH A FRESH,
VIBRANT FLAVOR.
THAT'S GOOD.
HOW MANY OYSTERS DOES
THE AVERAGE SHUCKER DO IN A DAY?
WE'LL GO THROUGH, LIKE,
ON A FRIDAY, A BUSY DAY,
ABOUT 25 SACKS.
THERE'S 120 OYSTERS
IN A SACK.
WOW, THAT'S
A LOT OF SHUCKIN'.
NO CHOICE.
A LOT OF THE REGULARS
CAN'T WAIT TO COME BACK,
WHICH MAKES IT PRETTY TOUGH
ON 'EM IN THE SUMMER.
THREE MONTHS?
YOU GUYS JUST--CLICK?
AND EVERYBODY GOES
ON VACATION?
UH-HUH.
EVERYBODY GETS DEPRESSED.
WE RIDE BY TO SEE
WHEN THE SIGN IS OUT
THAT THEY'RE GONNA
BE BACK.
LET'S FIND A SPOT.
IT LOOKS LIKE IT'S OPEN.
SO WHEN YOU COME,
YOU HAVE A COUPLE DOZEN RAW.
AND THEN THE LOAF,
AND THAT'S THE PERFECT TOUCH.
I HAD AN OYSTER LOAF.
OYSTER LOAF?
MM-HMM.
IT'S NOT
LIKE MEATLOAF, EITHER.
WHAT IT IS IS A MESS
OF FRESH FRIED OYSTERS
ON TWO SLABS OF FRESH BREAD.
WE OPEN 'EM EARLY
IN THE MORNING TO FRY.
SO YOU'RE SHUCKING FRESH
OYSTERS TO FRY, ALSO?
RIGHT.
PUT 'EM IN MY CORN FLOUR
AND MY SALT.
SO REAL PRECISE
MEASUREMENT TECHNIQUES?
JUST A HANDFUL.
OKAY.
WE'RE NOT GONNA HIT 'EM
IN THE EGG WASH OR ANYTHING?
UNH-UNH.
JUST DROP 'EM IN.
GET A BUNCH OF 'EM.
WE HAVE THESE THINGS
CALLED DEEP-FAT FRYERS.
MM-HMM.
OKAY.
JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA KEEP
DOIN' 'EM THE SAME WAY.
OH, YEAH.
OLD-FASHIONED POTS.
USE PURE LARD.
DON'T USE ANY KIND OF OIL.
THIS IS THE BREAD WE USE
RIGHT HERE.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I HAVE
SEEN A LOAF OF BREAD
NOT SLICED.
IT WAS ACTUALLY
MADE THIS MORNING.
AND I DON'T KNOW THAT
ON TRIPLE "D" I'VE SEEN ANYBODY
WHIP OUT THE HOLIDAY
CARVING KNIFE EITHER.
OH, YEAH.
BREAD COMES THIS SOFT...
THERE'S NO CUTTING IT
WITH ANYTHING ELSE.
THERE'S NO CUTTING
IT WITH ANYTHING ELSE.
IT WOULD JUST
PUSH IT DOWN.
TOAST IT UNDER
AN OPEN FIRE.
YOU TOAST BOTH SIDES.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
YOU CAN HAVE IT PLAIN,
OR YOU CAN HAVE IT DRESSED.
WOULD YOU LIKE IT DRESSED--
LETTUCE, TOMATO, MAYO?
(Guy) WHY DON'T WE MAKE ONE HALF
DRESSED AND ONE HALF PLAIN?
ONE HALF PLAIN?
I DON'T KNOW IF I CAN
GET THROUGH ONE HALF.
I FEEL THAT PHILLY HUNCH
COMIN' IN.
I MEAN--
A LITTLE PRIVACY?
OH. MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
BOY, THAT'S FRESH TASTING.
MM-HMM.
CAN'T GET ANY FRESHER.
THE ARM, IN CASE
YOU WANT SOME OF IT.
OH, GOOD.
IF ANYBODY TELLS ME THAT THEY
DON'T LIKE OYSTER SANDWICHES,
LET 'EM GO
TO CASAMENTO'S.
COME TO CASAMENTO'S.
I WANT TO HAVE THEM HAVE
A LITTLE TALK WITH C.J.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE PUT
ON THERE IS THAT TABASCO.
THAT REALLY KICKS IT.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL.
I LOVE THE WAY YOU LOAF.
I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF THE LOAF THING BEFORE.
IT'S REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
AND THEY'LL LOAF
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
(C.J.) SOME TROUT
COMIN' OUT.
SOME TROUT, TOO?
MM-HMM.
YOU HAVE THE CATFISH?
THE FRIED SHRIMP ARE WONDERFUL,
I THINK THE BEST IN THE CITY.
HOW MUCH SHRIMP
I GOT ON THERE?
NEVER FROZEN?
NO, FRESH.
MMM, THAT'S NICE.
GOT ANOTHER CRAB.
TWO CRABS.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB.
THEY ONLY COME OUT A CERTAIN
TIME, AND YOU HAVE TO CATCH THEM
BEFORE THEIR SHELL
STARTS TO HARDEN.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB?
DON'T LIKE
EGG AND MILK WASH?
RIGHT.
WAS THIS SOMETHING
YOUR GRANDPA WAS DOING?
THIS WAS ANOTHER ONE
OF HIS STAPLES HERE?
ANOTHER ONE OF 'EM.
GONNA PUT 'EM IN
MY CORN FLOUR AND MY SALT.
SO THEY COME RIGHT IN HERE.
GO INTO THE--
THAT LITTLE THING YOU
DID THERE WITH THE FLOUR
IS TO CHECK THE OIL TEMP.
CHECK THE OIL TEMP, RIGHT.
AND YOU ALWAYS WANT
TO COVER SOFT SHELLS.
'CAUSE THEY SPIT
A BUNCH
'CAUSE THERE'S SO MUCH
WATER INSIDE OF IT?
THEY'RE EXPELLING THAT
WATER OUT OF IT? RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, HERE ARE
THE SOFT SHELLS.
NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
BEAUTIFUL.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT THAT WHOLE
BAD BOY ON THERE?
RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT LIKE THAT.
THIS IS WHEN YOU NEED
THE HUNCH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OHH...
WHAT?
THAT IS DYNAMITE.
GREAT CRAB FLAVOR.
I'M GONNA GET THE REST TO GO.
I'M GONNA TAKE A NAP.
SOFT-SHELL CRABS
ARE DELICIOUS.
ANYTHING YOU GET HERE
IS PROBABLY
THE BEST YOU'RE GONNA GET
IN NEW ORLEANS.
THIS IS OUR FAVORITE.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
THERE'S NOTHIN'
LIKE LOOKIN' OUT THERE
AND WATCHIN' SOMEBODY
TAKE A BITE
AND WATCHIN' THE LOOK
ON THEIR FACE.
DOES EVERYBODY LOOK LIKE THIS
WHEN THEY EAT IT?
JUST ABOUT.
OKAY, GOOD.
I'M GONNA NEED YOU
TO STAND OVER THERE.
READY?
THERE IT IS.
I'LL BE PERFORMING HERE
ALL WEEK.
NEXT STOP, OMAHA...
FRIED CHICKEN UP.
FOR OLD-SCHOOL SOUL FOOD...
IT'S LIKE EATIN' AT HOME.
AND A FAVORITE...
PIG EARS.
I'M JUST DYING TO TRY.
EAT IT.
SO HERE I AM IN NORTH OMAHA
AT A PLACE CALLED
BIG MAMA'S KITCHEN.
NOW IT'S A SOUL FOOD JOINT
WHERE FOLKS SAY
SHE'S COOKIN' IT OLD-SCHOOL.
BUT THE FUNNY THING IS,
IT REALLY IS
IN AN OLD SCHOOL.
CORN BREAD SALAD, PLEASE.
I NEED THREE GREENS.
IT'S DEFINITELY
THE OLD SCHOOL.
CATFISH.
THEY'VE MADE IT FEEL
LIKE HOME.
YOU CAN TASTE THE LOVE
IN THE FOOD.
FRIED CHICKEN UP.
(woman) SWEET POTATO
PUDDING.
MMM, IT'S GOT SOUL.
OF THE CHARTS.
THIS IS THE WAY MY GRANDMOTHER
AND MY MOTHER COOKED.
AND NOW IT'S HER TURN.
I'M GLAD
YOU SHOWED UP.
PATRICIA BARRON
WHO CALLS HERSELF "BIG MAMA"...
WAS THERE ANY SIDES
WITH THIS?
IS BRINGIN' EVERYBODY
TO THE FAMILY TABLE.
WHOO.
AFTER A STINT
IN THE MILITARY
AND 30 YEARS
AT THE PHONE COMPANY,
SHE RETIRED TO DO
WHAT SHE ALWAYS WANTED.
I JUST LIKE TO COOK.
BUT SHE DIDN'T
HAVE A RESTAURANT.
I WAS COOKIN' OUT
OF MY CHURCH'S BASEMENT.
THEN SHE FOUND
SOMETHING BETTER...
CHICKEN'S READY TO GO.
THIS WAS THE NEBRASKA
SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF,
AND THIS WAS THE CAFETERIA.
IT CLOSED IN 1992.
WHAT A NICE FIND.
WHERE MAMA'S CRANKIN' OUT
SOUL FOOD CLASSICS...
CHITLINS.
SMOTHERED PORK CHOPS.
COLLARD GREENS
WITH BACON DRIPPINGS ON 'EM.
AND THAT SUNDAY
DINNER TRADITION.
IT'S HOW CHICKEN
USED TO BE.
I'M GONNA COOK CHICKEN
LIKE MY GRANDMA TAUGHT ME
HOW TO COOK CHICKEN.
WE'RE GONNA OVEN FRY IT.
OVEN FRIED?
I JUST POUR
THE BUTTERMILK ON IT.
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH ALL THE SEASONINGS?
YES.
THE LEMON PEPPER.
NO-SALT SEASONING.
A PACKAGED GROUP
OF SEASONINGS?
CORRECT.
AND THIS ONE HERE
LOOKS LIKE IT HAS
A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR OR SALT?
THAT'S MY RUB--
CUMIN, PAPRIKA,
CHILI POWDER.
LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE PAPRIKA THERE.
OKAY, SO WE LET THOSE
MARINATE?
I USUALLY LET IT
SIT OVERNIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, SO THIS IS MARINATED.
IT'S GOT THE RUB.
IT'S GOT EVERYBODY.
THIS IS SELF-RISING FLOUR.
REALLY GIVE 'EM--
A GOOD COATING.
WHAT YOU'RE DOING THERE
IS YOU'RE FOLDING THAT WING
INTO ITSELF AND THEN
IT DOESN'T HAVE A TENDENCY
TO DRY OUT AS MUCH.
IT'S LIKE CHICKEN YOGA.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT
IN THE OIL?
THAT'S CORRECT.
I USE CANOLA OIL.
THAT'S THE BEST OIL.
AND THAT'S GONNA GO IN
THE CONVECTION OVEN AND GET HOT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MOVE BACK A LITTLE BIT.
WE DO IT VERY CAREFUL.
YES, WE DO.
SKIN SIDE DOWN.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE PART
FO THE CHICKEN?
THE BREAST.
I HAD FIVE BROTHERS
AND SISTERS.
I NEVER GOT THE BREAST.
YEAH, I'M A WING GUY.
MY MOM ALWAYS HAD THE WING.
MY DAD HAD THE BREAST.
MY SISTER GOT THE DRUMSTICK,
'CAUSE SHE WHINED.
WE WANT TO FRY IT 15 MINUTES.
THEN I TURN IT.
AND THEN COOK 15 MINUTES
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
IT'S BAKED WHILE IT FRIES.
NOW I KNOW WE'RE GONNA ARM
WRESTLE FOR THE THIGH.
NO. THE BREAST.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S EAT IT.
MMM, THAT'S
PRETTY TASTY.
IT'S AWESOME.
GOOD CHICKEN.
MOIST, FLAVORFUL, YOU GET
THE TASTE OF THE CHICKEN.
THE BREADING ISN'T
TAKING ALL THE POWER.
MMM, HAVING SOME
OF THAT THIGH, HUH?
I'M GONNA TRY IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU CONVINCED ME.
I LIKE THE BREAST BETTER.
IT'S GOT A CRUST ON IT
THAT'S EXCELLENT.
SEASONED VERY WELL, AND IT
DEFINITELY TASTES HOMEMADE.
FAMILY MEALS AT HOME WAS USUALLY
SOMETHING VERY SIMILAR.
AND WHY NOT?
IT'S THE KIND OF COOKIN'
BIG MAMA GREW UP WITH.
IT HAS A NICE
SOUTHERN FEEL TO IT.
ORIGINALLY FROM
MISSISSIPPI.
WE EAT A LOT OF GREENS.
COLLARD GREENS.
MMM, GOOD GREENS.
FRIED OKRA.
EVEN THIS SOUL FOOD CLASSIC--
CHITLINS.
VERY TENDER.
THESE ARE EXCELLENT.
EVERYTHING IS PHENOMENAL.
I'M ALWAYS LOOKIN'
WHEN I GO PLACES,
PICKIN' UP ON DIFFERENT
FOODS THAT PEOPLE EAT.
(woman) HERE'S
YOUR AFRO BURGER.
SHE PICKED THIS ONE UP
DURING A CHURCH MISSION TRIP
TO AFRICA.
VERY HOT AND SPICY.
I LOVE SPICY FOODS.
NOW IT'S STARTING TO GET HOT.
SO THIS IS, LIKE,
UP THERE.
THAT WORKS FOR YOU?
OH, YEAH.
LET'S MAKE SOME
AFRO BURGERS.
THIS IS THE BEST BEEF.
THIS IS 10 POUNDS OF ANGUS BEEF.
ALL THIS PEPPER IS GONNA
GO IN 10 POUNDS?
OH, YEAH.
IF YOU DON'T LIKE SPICY FOOD,
YOU WON'T LIKE THIS DISH.
BREADCRUMBS...
ALL OF THE PEPPER AVAILABLE
IN THE WESTERN UNITED STATES.
FRESH RED PEPPERS...
SUGAR?
BROWN SUGAR,
CHOPPED VIDALIA ONIONS...
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET.
CHILI POWDER,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
THIS IS NUTMEG.
THIS IS CINNAMON.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
THE SALT.
WE'VE GOT 9 POUNDS
OF HOT CHILI FLAKES
MIXED INTO 2 POUNDS OF MEAT.
WE'RE GOING TO COMMENCE
THE PROCESS
OF BURNING OUR
PALATE OFF.
THAT GIVES IT PIZZAZZ.
EGG? NOW WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO?
WE HAVE TO WEIGH IT UP
INTO 6-OUNCE BALLS.
IT'S A LITTLE OVER, BUT--
I DON'T WANT TO BE
KICKED OUT OF CAMP.
DEAD ON.
TAKE ONE OF THE BALLS
AND YOU FLATTEN IT,
THEN FOLD IT OVER.
FOLD THE PAPER BACK
AND THEN ROLL IT.
OKAY, THEN WE WRAP THIS
IN CELLOPHANE.
WE ROLL ONE TIME,
THEN WE FOLD.
AND THEN ROLL,
ROLL, ROLL.
OKAY.
NO, THAT--DID YOU
SEE ME DO IT LIKE THAT?
YOU WANT IT TO LOCK IN
AS WE ROLL IT.
YOU WANT TO RACE
THIS TIME?
AND HE'S FIRST
INTO THE PLASTIC.
HUH? WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU'RE OKAY.
I MIGHT HIRE YOU.
PUT 'EM IN THE FREEZER
TILL WE'RE READY TO COOK 'EM.
THESE ARE ALL
NICE AND FROZEN.
THOSE GOTTA GO DOWN FOR
A LONG TIME THOUGH, HUH?
OH, ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
OKAY, SO YOU UNWRAP IT.
AND THEN SOAK 'EM
IN THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
WELCOME
TO THE AFRO BURGER.
LOOK AT ALL THAT SPICE
RIGHT IN THERE.
WOW! THAT IS HOT.
YES.
YOU'RE TURNIN' RED.
THAT IS SPICY,
BIG MAMA.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
I LIKE HOT FOOD.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M SPEAKING LOUDER.
MMM, THAT'S SOMETHING
TO COME FOR.
(whistles)
LOVE IT.
THERE'S SOME SPICE
IN THAT THING.
YEAH, I CAN HANDLE IT.
THE HOTTER,
THE BETTER.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
BUT IF YOU WANT UNIQUE...
(man) PIG EARS.
AND I'LL HAVE
A PIG EAR.
COMIN' UP NEXT.
EAT IT.
AT BIG MAMA'S IN OMAHA,
THEY'RE COOKIN' IT OLD-SCHOOL.
LITERALLY.
IT'S KIND OF A STRANGE PLACE,
THOUGH, DON'T YOU THINK?
COMIN' TO THE SCHOOL?
BUT IT'S NO SCHOOL LUNCH.
WHEN I COME HERE,
IT'S LIKE EATIN' AT HOME.
A LOT OF THE FOOD THAT
SHE COOKS IS FROM THE SOUTH.
FRIED OKRA.
PIG EARS.
YOU'VE NEVER HAD
A PIG EAR?
I HEARD...
YOU'RE HAVIN'
THE EAR SANDWICH.
I AM.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
DON'T FEAR THE EAR.
LET'S GET IT ON.
OKAY.
I LIKE TO EXAMINE 'EM.
OOH, THOSE ARE FRESH.
THERE'S NO HAIRS.
SEE? THAT'S GRISTLE.
JUST A TICKLE OF MEAT
THERE.
I KNOW IT.
I KNOW, DON'T PLAY
WITH YOUR FOOD.
AND THEN I'M GONNA PUT IT
IN MY CROCK-POT.
MM-HMM,
SALTIN' UP THAT EAR.
GRANDMA'S RUB, A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR, SALT.
CUMIN, PAPRIKA,
CHILI POWDER.
THEY'RE VERY PLAIN, SO THEY NEED
A LOT OF SEASONING ON 'EM.
THEN THE GARLIC.
THEN ADD MY WATER.
OH.
ADD A LITTLE VINEGAR.
IT'LL GO DOWN
FOR ABOUT EIGHT HOURS.
COVER THAT UP,
PLUG IT IN.
AND I PUT 'EM ON LOW.
YOU KNOW WHAT? I JUST--
TIME HAS GOT AWAY FROM ME.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO GO.
I'LL BE BACK "EAR"
LATER.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
YOU WANT TO EAT 'EM NOW.
RIGHT "EAR,"
RIGHT NOW.
THIS'LL BE THE HIGHLIGHT
OF YOUR DAY.
I'M EXCITED.
LET'S JUST DO THIS.
YOU BE AS LIBERAL WITH
THAT MUSTARD AS YOU WANT.
THERE YOU GO.
EXTRA, EXTRA.
CHOPPED ONION,
THAT GIVES IT
A LITTLE ZING.
THAT DOESN'T LOOK BAD,
RIGHT?
NO.
I MEAN, THAT PART--
THAT DOESN'T--
THAT SCARES ME.
WELL, JUST BITE IT.
THAT'S ALL.
EAT IT.
DON'T PUSH IT
IN MY MOUTH.
YOU'RE EXCITED
TO SEE ME EAT THIS.
YES, I AM,
BECAUSE I KNOW
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE IT.
IT'S TENDER.
IT IS TENDER.
SEE? THE CARTILAGE COOKED
DOWN TO A NICE TENDER STATE.
IT IS VERY TASTY.
I WOULD CALL IT
"NATURAL BOLOGNA."
I DIDN'T REALLY THINK I WAS
GONNA BE TOO BIG OF A FAN.
ONCE YOU'RE "EAR,"
YOU LOVE IT.
REALLY MOIST,
AND NOT TOUGH AT ALL.
THIS PIG EAR SANDWICH--
YUM-YUM.
I WOULD RECOMMEND IT.
TRUE SOUL FOOD CLASSIC.
SOUL AND FAMILY
GO TOGETHER.
FEELS LIKE HOME.
LIKE I REMEMBER
WHEN I WAS A KID.
IT'S LEGIT, HUH?
IT'S LEGIT.
WHEN IT'S MEANT TO BE,
THINGS LIKE THIS JUST HAPPEN.
YES, IT CERTAINLY DOES.
I'M LOOKIN' FOR MY MOTHER
TO COME OUT THE KITCHEN.
I WANT TO SPREAD MY FOOD
ALL OVER THE CITY.
I WANT EVERYBODY
TO COME AND ENJOY MY FOOD.
GOOD STUFF.
I ENJOYED IT.
GOOD. I'M GLAD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE-D--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THE BREAST GETS DRIED OUT.
THAT'S BECAUSE
YOU OVERCOOK IT.
WELL, YOU'RE NOT COOKIN'
THE THIGH ENOUGH.
AND IT'S NOT AS TASTY.
NOT AS TASTY?
NO.
I'M OUTTA HERE.