HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
ORDERS UP.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ALLIGATOR BITES
ARE AWESOME.
DOIN' THEIR OWN THING.
IT'S SALT LAKE CITY...
I FEEL LIKE I WALKED
INTO A FIESTA.
I LOVE THIS.
A TAQUERIA...
FISH TACO UP.
SERVIN' UP SHARK...
OKAY, BOYS.
AND MONSTER BURRITOS...
NOTHIN' BETTER.
WITH A LITTLE
OF EVERYTHING.
DO YOU WANT A BITE?
NAH, I'M DRIVIN'.
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
OLD WORLD WITH
A MODERN FLAIR.
COMFORT FOOD
WITH A TWIST.
PORK ROAST DONE WITH
THE POLENTA AND THE BEANS.
MM-HMM. IT'S DELICIOUS.
LAMB BURGER.
(man) VERY FLAVORFUL,
VERY SPICY, WONDERFUL.
MMM! DELICIOUS. WOW.
I'D EAT THAT ALL DAY.
CLEANIN' MYSELF LIKE A CAT.
AND IN OMAHA...
THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
NEW YORK DELI...
IT'S FANTASTIC.
CANADIAN STYLE.
EXCELLENT,
PERFECTLY JUICY.
THAT'S THE COUSIN
OF CORNED BEEF AND PASTRAMI
THAT LIVES
IN CANADA, EH?
AND, HEY, PASS
THE ALLIGATOR BITES.
YOU JUST DON'T FIND GOOD
ALLIGATOR EVERY DAY,
NOW DO YA?
NOT IN OMAHA.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
USUALLY ON TRIPLE "D," YOU SEE
ME CRUISIN' THE CONVERTIBLE '67,
BUT WHEN I FIND A JOINT
THAT'S GOT A CAR THIS SICK,
WELL, I JUST GOTTA STOP
AND CHECK IT OUT,
AND IT'S NOT JUST
THE CAR THAT'S UNIQUE
HERE AT THE LONE STAR TAQUERIA
IN SALT LAKE CITY.
THEY'RE DOIN' MEXICAN FOOD
THE REAL-DEAL WAY.
ANOTHER CHICKEN
MORENO CILANTRO.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SALSA, EVERYBODY'S FINE?
GREAT.
ORDER'S UP, PLEASE.
CASUAL AND FUNKY.
THE CAR AND THE BOOTS
REALLY STUCK OUT.
OKAY, BOYS.
THERE'S NO OTHER
PLACE LIKE IT.
(man) FISH TACO WITH
TWO STEAK TACOS, OKAY?
UN QUESADILLA SOLAMENTE.
AND IS IT
ALWAYS THIS CHAOTIC?
YEAH.
I FEEL LIKE I WALKED
INTO A FIESTA.
TWO FISH TACOS.
THE FOOD'S FABULOUS.
PRETTY MUCH AWESOMENESS.
ENJOY THE FISH TACO?
YES, IT'S MONEY.
EVERYBODY'S HAPPY?
'CAUSE THIS AIN'T
SUSAN HARRIES' FIRST RODEO.
IT'S ALL I'VE DONE
SINCE I WAS THE AGE 13.
TACO DE PESCADO.
AFTER RUNNING
ALL KINDS OF RESTAURANTS,
SHE WANTED TO OPEN
A MEXICAN PLACE.
CARNE ADOVADA?
RIGHT HERE.
SO SHE BROUGHT IN
AN OLD FRIEND, MANUEL VALDEZ...
THE FISH TACO UP.
AND HIS BROTHER...
CHICKEN BURRITO.
TO DO THE FOOD
THEY GREW UP WITH.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
I MEAN,
IT'S LIKE FAMILY.
IT'S AWESOME.
WHERE I COME FOR TACOS.
BIG, BIG BURRITOS.
I'VE JUST BEEN TURNED ON
TO THE CARNE ADOVADA.
CARNE AV--ADOVADA.
(man) TWO ADOVADA BURRITOS.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
THIS IS PERFECT.
WITH THE ADOVADA,
WE USE THE SHOULDER.
THE PORK BUTT.
YEP.
NICE AND THIN, RIGHT.
WE CLEAN IT.
GET ALL
THE SILVER SKIN OFF.
AND THEN
WE THIN IT OUT.
LOOK AT YOU, MAN. YOU ARE
JUST A BUTCHERING MACHINE.
IT'S NOT YOUR
FIRST TIME, HUH?
NO.
SO HE COMES IN AND PULLS IT OFF
ONE TIME, FLAPS IT OVER,
AND THEN HE
TURNS IT AROUND
AND COMES AND PULLS
IT OFF THE OTHER TIME.
THAT'S PERFECT.
MUY BIEN.
WHAT HAPPENS IS HE TOOK THREE
FOLDS OUT OF IT. (clicks tongue)
SEE?
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL?
YEP, EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MARINATE IT--CUMIN...
OKAY, CAYENNE.
CAYENNE.
THE GARLIC...
CALIFORNIA CHILI.
CALIFORNIA,
NEW MEXICO, CLOVE.
NOW YOU NEVER GRIND UP
THE CLOVE?
WE PUT IT WHOLE.
BAY LEAF, SALT.
UH-HUH.
ACEITE, THE OIL.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU WERE EXPECTING
THE FLAVOR TOWN REFERENCE.
I KNOW YOU WERE.
(laughs)
NOW WE USE
OUR HANDS, OKAY?
NO, WE DON'T.
YOU DO.
IT SIT, LIKE,
MAYBE OVERNIGHT.
YOU GONNA
GRILL THIS, OR...
NO, YOU'RE GONNA
PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
FOR HOW LONG?
FOR A COUPLE HOURS. YOU NEED
TO GET IT REALLY NICE AND SOFT.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR THIS.
ALL THE COOKING IS DONE,
MANUEL, IN THIS LITTLE KITCHEN?
LITT--YEAH.
THIS IS IT?
THIS IS IT.
OH, OH, OH,
OH, OH, OHH.
WE GOT A PIECE.
SEE HOW TENDER IT IS?
GO AHEAD
AND TRY A PIECE.
OH, THAT'S KILLER.
WE'RE GONNA DO
A TACO FOR YOU.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
COOK IT AGAIN.
NOW WE JUST--
PUT A LITTLE BIT
MORE CRISP ON IT.
YEAH, CRISPIN' ON IT.
SO WE JUST DO TWO TORTILLAS.
EVERYBODY LOVES
THIS ONE?
OH, YEAH, THEY LOVE ADOVADA.
WE BRING IT OVER.
OH, OHH!
THEN WE ADD
A LITTLE CILANTRO.
A LITTLE ONION.
AND THEN, ALSO,
A LITTLE OF THE LIME.
THAT'S IT. YOU DON'T
MESS WITH--MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GREAT.
FLAVOR IS AMAZING.
WHY EVEN HAVE
THE TORTILLA?
JUST SERVE IT IN MY HAND
OR IN MY SHOE OR IN MY POCKET.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THEY
DO TO IT, BUT IT'S REALLY GOOD.
SPICY FROM
INSIDE AND OUT.
HOW'S THE CARNE ASADA?
SO GOOD.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
IT'S VERY BIG.
THAT'S A LOT OF EATS.
I KNOW,
BUT IT'S GOOD.
DID YOU REALLY ORDER THAT?
THAT'S HALF THE SIZE OF YOU!
GOTTA GET
THE FOOTBALL HOLD.
THAT'S MONEY.
YOU WANT A BITE?
NAH, I'M DRIVIN'.
AND SOME OF THE BIGGEST
FAVORITES HERE...
FISH TACO COMBO UP.
ARE SEAFOOD...
NOTHIN' BETTER.
IN UTAH.
IS IT EASY TO GET
FRESH SEAFOOD HERE?
OH, YES, IT IS.
REALLY?
EVERY DAY.
QUESO PESCADO AHORITA.
FRESH AHI.
I'M HAVING A SALMON TACO.
THAT IS SOME
GOOD TACO. WOW.
THE SALMON'S THE BEST.
I REALLY LIKE
HALIBUT, TOO.
SOMETIMES IT'S COD,
SOMETIMES IT'S SOLE.
SEA BASS...
IT'S KINDA
LIKE ROULETTE.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA GET THAT DAY.
I GOT THE SHARK TACO.
THIS IS THE ONE
I'M REALLY EXCITED FOR. MMM.
THAT'S THE ONE
RIGHT THERE.
YOU TELL ME THAT YOU'RE GONNA
FIND THE AVERAGE TAQUERIA
THAT'S GOT SHARK TACOS...
MAHIMAHI,
RED SNAPPER...
OKAY, I'M RUNNING
OUT OF FINGERS.
THEY HAVE EVERYTHING.
CAMARONES.
SHRIMP BURRITO.
THIS ONE'S
ON THE MENU EVERY DAY.
I HAVE TO HAVE THESE
AT LEAST REGULARLY.
SO GOOD.
YOU MAKE SEPARATE VEGETABLES
FOR THE SHRIMP TACO
AND SHRIMP BURRITO?
WE USE BELL PEPPERS,
RED ONION--
JULIENNE?
JULIENNE, PERFECT.
THEY'RE NOT TO BE BEAUTIFUL.
THEY'RE JUST TO GET DONE.
NO--YES. EXACTAMENTE.
SO NOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO IS
GONNA ADD ALL THE INGREDIENTS.
MM-HMM, GARLIC, CAYENNE,
A LOT OF PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ALL IN?
(indistinct speech)
CALIFORNIA CHILI...
SOME SALT.
SOME SALT,
NEW MEXICO CHILI.
THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF THE...
SOYBEAN OIL.
SOYBEAN OIL!
SOYBEAN.
WOW, HOW... OF YOU.
MM-HMM.
SO WE SAUTé THAT UP.
TAKES, WHAT, TWO HOURS?
MAYBE LESS, BUT,
YOU KNOW, AROUND THERE.
WOW, LOOK HOW MUCH
THAT'S COOKED DOWN.
WOW, IT'S GREAT FLAVOR.
(whistles) A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT ON THAT.
LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
GONNA TRY A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC IN THERE.
WE GO FAST
WITH THESE RIGHT?
YEP. NOW WE HAVE
OUR PEPPERS.
YOU GOT JUICE
ALREADY ANYWAY, TOO.
TORTILLA.
(whistles)
BIG TORTILLA RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'VE GOT OUR RICE.
WE'VE GOT SOME OF OUR BEANS.
AND THOSE FRIJOLES,
WE GOT MANTECA IN THAT OR...
NO, VEGETABLE OIL,
CUMIN, GARLIC AND SALT.
OKAY.
AND YOU'RE DONE.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF CHEESE.
NOW THE CAMARONES.
I JUST
PUT A LITTLE--
DON'T FORGET THAT GUY.
OH, THAT GUY
RIGHT THERE, HUH?
CILANTRO, I GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF ONIONS, JUST FRESH ONIONS,
TOMATOES, GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF LETTUCE.
LOOKS GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT OF SOUR CREAM
HERE. OH, NO, NO, NO.
GO ALL THE WAY OVER.
THAT WAY YOU BRING THIS BACK.
THEN YOU BRING THAT
ONE BACK. OH, OKAY.
AND THEN ROLL OVER.
IT'S LIKE THE TAQUITO METHOD.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
I HAVE TO BE ABLE TO SEE IT.
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
WHAT'S THAT CALLED?
KILLER BURRITO? REALLY GOOD.
SHRIMP ARE NICE
AND TENDER.
YOU DEFINITELY GET THE DISTINCT
FLAVOR OF THE PEPPERS.
I GOT NOTHIN'
BUT HAPPY ON THAT.
SERIOUSLY, AWESOME.
AWESOME!
NICE AND SPICY,
LOTS OF INTERESTING PEPPERS.
IT'S GOT
A KICK TO IT.
I LOVE IT.
YOU GUYS GOOD?
YOU EAT THE FOOD,
AND YOU'RE HOOKED.
TACO ASADA COMBO.
NORMALLY IN MEXICO, I'D
BE EATING THIS ON A STREET.
YOU JUST HAVE TO KEEP
COMIN' BACK.
BEST TACOS YOU'LL
EAT IN UTAH, FOR SURE.
IS THAT YOUR CAR?
NO.
THE CAMARO FOR
THE STATION WAGON--EVEN SWAP.
OH, IT--ABSOLUTELY NOT.
OKAY, I'LL GIVE
YOU 500 BUCKS.
UP NEXT...
(man) COMIN' AT YA.
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO MINNEAPOLIS...
LAMB BURGER.
TO A PLACE DOIN'
THE OLD STUFF...
OLD WORLD WITH
A MODERN FLAIR.
THEIR WAY.
WE DON'T REALLY
WORK WITH RECIPES.
MOST OF IT COMES OUT
OF OUR HEADS.
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
THE NORTHEAST SECTION
OF MINNEAPOLIS
IS ONE
OF THE CITY'S OLDEST.
IN THE LATE 1800s,
IT WAS A BOOMING INDUSTRIAL
AREA, AND YOU CAN STILL SEE
THE HISTORY
IN THE BUILDINGS TODAY,
JUST LIKE THIS PLACE
WE'RE CHECKIN' OUT.
NOW ON THE OUTSIDE
IT MAY SAY OLD SCHOOL,
BUT ON THE INSIDE, THE MENU
AND THE CULINARY ATTITUDE
ARE WHAT THE NAME
SAYS OUT FRONT.
OLD WORLD
WITH A MODERN FLAIR.
(man) POT ROAST GNOCCHI
COMIN' AT YA.
THE FOOD
IS ALWAYS FANTASTIC.
(woman) INTERESTING
COMBINATIONS.
TROUT.
PAN-FRIED TROUT
WITH SWEET PORK--
NEVER WOULD HAVE PUT
THESE TOGETHER ON MY OWN,
BUT I LIKE
THE COMBINATION.
LAMB BURGER.
THIS IS A LAMB BURGER
WITH SPICY TOMATO
AND WONDERFUL
LAMB PATTY.
PORK ROAST DONE WITH
THE POLENTA AND THE BEANS.
MM-HMM,
BUT IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S GOOD UPSCALE DINING.
GOIN' GREAT.
TURNED THAT WAY
BY A NEIGHBORHOOD GUY
ON A MISSION.
I SAW PEOPLE THAT
WERE JUST LIKE ME,
WALKIN' AROUND--THERE
WAS NO PLACE FOR US TO EAT.
SO IN '94, AFTER A DECADE
OF COOKIN'
IN HIGH-END PLACES...
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT
HERE, PEOPLE?
FABULOUS.
JIM GRELL
BOUGHT THE MODERN
AND STARTED FEEDING
HIS NEIGHBORS HIS WAY.
RICHARD, YOU'RE
HAVING THE CHOCOLATE.
THIS WAS GONNA BE
YOUR CONTEMPORARY DINER,
IF YOU WANT
TO CALL IT THAT.
I WAS--YEAH.
I DECIDED TO MAKE FOOD THAT
WE ALL KNEW WITH A FUNKY TWIST.
(man)
MACARONI AND CHEESE.
THEY CHANGE THE MENU
FAIRLY OFTEN.
ABOUT EVERY
MONTH OR TWO.
DROPPIN' A GNOCCHI.
AND FOR HEAD CHEF
PHILLIP BECHT...
TWO MINUTES
ON A GNOCCHI.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
KEEPIN' THINGS FRESH.
WE DON'T REALLY
WORK WITH RECIPES.
MOST OF IT COMES
OUT OF OUR HEADS.
WITH FLAVORS
FROM EVERYWHERE...
IT'S ALWAYS IMAGINATIVE.
LIKE CHICKEN WINGS
IN HOISIN SAUCE...
THEY'RE AMAZING.
SMOKED HADDOCK RAVIOLI,
EVEN A NORTH AFRICAN-STYLE
LAMB BURGER.
VERY FLAVORFUL,
VERY SPICY, WONDERFUL.
THIS IS LAMB SHOULDER--
COMES FROM MINNESOTA.
SO IT'S COOL THAT
WE GET TO USE IT.
SO LAMB SHOULDER AND...
THAT IS BEEF CHUCK 'CAUSE I WANT
TO GET SOME FAT IN THERE.
OH, YOU HAVE TO.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
CIRCA COLUMBUS?
WE'LL START THIS UP.
DO YOU NEED ME
TO HAND CRANK THAT, OR...
INTERESTING.
SO I JUST KINDA
MIX IT AS WE GO--
A LITTLE LAMB,
A LITTLE BEEF, GARLIC.
NOW YOU GOT CUMIN,
SOME CINNAMON.
YEP.
SMOKED SPANISH PAPRIKA,
A NICE FLAVOR.
AND A LITTLE
LEMON ZEST.
OKAY, SO SOME
FRESH HERBS GO DOWN...
YEP.
SO YOU DO
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY,
CILANTRO, LITTLE MINT,
SOME MORE MEAT.
YEAH.
SO YOU'RE JUST KINDA
GOING IN THIS ROTATION--
HERBS, MEAT, SPICES,
HERBS, MEAT, SPICES.
RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT, THAT'S
WHERE IT'S COMING OUT
WITH A LOT OF THE SEASONINGS
INCORPORATED RIGHT INTO IT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
GONNA SERVE THIS WITH?
TOMATO CHUTNEY THAT
WE'VE BEEN MESSIN' WITH.
TOMATO CHUTNEY.
LET'S MAKE SOME OF THAT.
WE'LL START
WITH CLARIFIED BUTTER,
MINCED-UP CARROTS
AND SOME ONIONS.
THIS IS GONNA COOK
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
NOW WE HIT A LITTLE
SUN-DRIED TOMATO?
YEAH, AND THEN A FEW
CHOPPED TOMATO, GOLDEN RAISINS.
'CAUSE YOU ALMOST THINK
THAT EVERY CHUTNEY'S
GOTTA HAVE
RAISINS IN IT.
YOU GOTTA HAVE SWEET.
SOME CURRY POWDER,
SOME GARAM MASALA,
SOME CLOVE,
DARK-BROWN SUGAR.
SO THAT WILL GIVE IT
A NICE MOLASSES-Y--
MOLA--IS MOLASSES-Y
A WORD?
MOLASS-A-LISTIC?
OH, THAT'S COOL.
AND THEN WE JUST
ADD CHOPPED CILANTRO,
SOME SCALLIONS
AND SOME TOASTED ALMONDS.
AND THEN IT'S JUST OFF
TO THE SHEET TRAY TO COOL.
SO THIS IS
OUR LAMB BURGER.
A TOUCH OF OIL,
NOW ON THE GRILL.
WOW, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
NOW ARE WE GONNA GET
SOME FOCACCIA DOWN,
PUT A LITTLE TOAST
ON IT OR...
YEP, PUT A LITTLE
BIBB LETTUCE ON,
SOME TZATZIKI, RED ONION,
TAKE THE BURGER FROM THE GRILL
AND THEN THE CHUTNEY.
THAT LOOKS TOO GOOD
TO EVEN BREAK INTO.
WOW.
THAT'S GOT
SOME RIDICULOUS FLAVOR,
BUT THE THING THAT I LIKE
THE BEST ABOUT IT--MMM--
IS HOW JUICY IT IS.
LOOK AT THAT
RIGHT THERE.
THE CHUTNEY'S GOT A LITTLE
SWEETNESS, A LITTLE TANG. MMM.
NEXT TIME I COME INTO TOWN
AND YOU DON'T HAVE THAT
ON THE MENU, I'M GONNA HUNT YOU
DOWN AND--THIS IS FANTASTIC.
I LOVE THE TOPPING.
THE TOMATO CHUTNEY?
YEAH.
(whistles)
EVERYTHING
COMES OUT GOOD.
THIS RESTAURANT NEVER
DOES ANYTHING HALFWAY.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE WAY
JIM FIXED THE PLACE UP...
IT'S TOTALLY CHARMING.
TAKIN' THE MODERN
BACK IN TIME.
IT'S BEEN FUN OVER THE YEARS
TO EXPLORE AND, YOU KNOW,
LEARN WHAT
A '40s DINER WAS.
THEY HAVE KINDA
OLD FAVORITES--THE POT ROAST.
REMINDS ME OF, YOU KNOW,
HOME COOKING.
BUT WITH A TWIST,
LIKE SERVING STRIP STEAK
WITH TABBOULEH
OR GNOCCHI WITH
OYSTER MUSHROOMS AND PEAS...
HERE'S YOUR ROAST PORK.
AND PORK ROAST ON GRILLED
POLENTA WITH BLACK BEANS.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY,
REALLY NICE.
WANT TO TRY THIS?
YOU SO WANT TO TRY THIS.
IT'S NOTHING I WOULD THINK
OF PUTTING TOGETHER MYSELF,
BUT IT'S
A REALLY GREAT MIX.
AND YOU'RE ENJOYING
THE WINGS HOISIN?
ABSOLUTELY.
VERY SPICY,
BUT THEY'RE WORTH IT.
LOOKIN' GOOD
ON THOSE, HUH?
THEY'RE GONNA GET TOSSED AROUND
IN SOME HOISIN BARBEQUE SAUCE.
MMM!
DELICIOUS. WOW,
I'D EAT THAT ALL DAY.
CLEANIN' MYSELF
LIKE A CAT.
WHAT ELSE WAS ENTICING
TO YOU ON THE MENU?
THE FISH CAKES
LOOKED REALLY GOOD.
HOW ARE
THE FISH CAKES?
THEY'RE FANTASTIC!
I LOVE THE COLOR.
THE BEST FISH CAKE
I'VE EVER HAD.
SALMON AND HADDOCK?
ICELANDIC HADDOCK.
OKAY.
WE JUST CUT THE FISH INTO
SOME KIND OF WORKABLE CUBES.
THE CUBES GO INTO THIS, AND THEN
JUST LIKE TWO, THREE TIMES.
THAT'S COOL. ALL RIGHT,
SO IT JUST ALL GOES IN.
TRI-COLOR BELL PEPPERS.
CARROTS, RED ONIONS,
JALAPEÑO,
SOME CHOPPED DILL.
A LITTLE BIT OF BREAD
AND HEAVY CREAM?
HEAVY CREAM, YEP,
GROUND GINGER, LEMON ZEST,
SOME CHILI FLAKES, SCALLIONS
AND SOME ORANGE PEEL,
WHOLE EGG,
SALT AND SOME PEPPER.
SO THEN YOU JUST
GET IN THERE AND GET GOIN'.
PRETTY MUCH EVERYBODY
IN THE GARDEN IN THE POOL.
BREADCRUMBS?
YEAH, NOW WE'RE READY
TO MAKE A CAKE.
SO JUST TOSS IT ON...
HIT A LITTLE BIT OF THE SEMOLINA
ON THE OUTSIDE.
AND THAT'S THAT.
ARE THESE GONNA GET
DEEP-FRIED, PAN-FRIED...
PAN-FRIED.
START WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF BUTTER AND THE CAKES.
AS SOON
AS WE TURN 'EM,
THEY'LL GO INTO THE OVEN
FOR A WHILE TO FINISH COOKING.
LET IT FINISH
WITH FULL HEAT.
YEAH.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT ON
THE BEET-GINGER PURéE, RIGHT?
LOOK AT THAT COLOR.
PURéE GOES DOWN
RIGHT ON THE BOTTOM.
SO...
BAD BOYS ARE READY?
KNOB OF BUTTER.
LOOK AT THAT.
IS IT TENDER? BEYOND.
THE VEGGIES
STILL HAVE CRUNCH.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE HAD
A FISH CAKE THAT GOOD.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I FINISHED THAT
WHOLE PLATE LIKE THAT.
I WOULD TOTALLY GET
THIS AGAIN AND AGAIN.
IT'S JUST ONE
OF MY FAVORITE PLACES.
I'VE NEVER
BEEN DISAPPOINTED.
I'VE GOTTA SAY, EVERYTHING
I'VE TRIED ON THE MENU,
I'VE BEEN
BLOWN AWAY, TOO.
IT'S JUST PLAIN GOOD
ALL THE TIME.
(Phillip) TWO POT ROASTS.
IF YOU WERE GOING
TO GIVE US JUST ONE WORD
THAT WOULD DESCRIBE MODERN--
COMMUNITY, ACTUALLY.
COMMUNITY--I BELIEVE IN IT.
IT LOOKS OLD-SCHOOL OUTSIDE,
BUT THE ATTITUDE
AND THE ENERGY--JUST LIKE
THE SIGN SAYS, IT IS MODERN.
THANKS.
BEAUTIFUL, MAN.
NEXT UP...
ORDERS UP.
WE'RE GOIN' TO OMAHA...
FANTASTIC.
EXCELLENT.
FOR WHAT LOOKS LIKE
A NEW YORK DELI SANDWICH...
MMM.
BUT FROM CANADA.
A DUDE FROM
MONTREAL MAKIN'...
CANADIAN SMOKED MEAT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA.
IT'S DEFINITELY
MORE THAN I EXPECTED.
EH, IT ALL
MAKES SENSE TO ME.
SO HERE I AM
IN THE HEART OF NEBRASKA
AT A PLACE WHOSE
FRENCH-CANADIAN CHEF
IS MAKIN' A CANADIAN VERSION
OF A NEW YORK PASTRAMI SANDWICH
IN OMAHA!
IT'S FANTASTIC.
EXCELLENT.
PERFECTLY JUICY.
THIN SLICED,
STACKED REAL HIGH.
KILLER!
A SPICY
SMOKED DELI MEAT...
IT'S ALREADY UP THERE.
THAT OWNER YVES MENARD
GREW UP EATIN' IN CANADA.
I GOTCHA.
A LOCAL FAVORITE
CREATED IN MONTREAL'S
JEWISH IMMIGRANT COMMUNITY
IN THE LATE 1800s.
I MISS MY SMOKED MEAT SANDWICH
THAT WE HAVE IN MONTREAL.
SO HE OPENED THIS JOINT TO
SERVE HIS CHILDHOOD FAVORITE...
OH, THAT'S ONION RING.
AND A FEW OTHER THINGS,
LIKE BURGERS AND BEER.
SO THEY CALL
THIS PLACE BREWBURGERS.
A DUDE FROM
MONTREAL MAKIN'...
CANADIAN SMOKED MEAT
IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA.
IT'S AN OLD-FASHIONED
BRISKET SANDWICH.
CURED IN A BRINE
LIKE CORNED BEEF
AND SMOKED LIKE PASTRAMI.
EH, IT ALL
MAKES SENSE TO ME.
IT'S JUST
AMAZING FLAVORS.
SO WE'RE GONNA GET
THAT BRINE STARTED.
FROG POWDER, WHICH IS SALT
WITH THE DEXTROSE IN IT,
KOSHER SALT, STANDARD
PICKLING SPICE.
PICKLING SPICE WITH
SOME PEPPERCORN, FENNEL,
MUSTARD SEED AND A LITTLE
BIT OF BAY LEAF.
AND A LITTLE
BIT OF CLOVE.
SO WE'LL GIVE
THAT A MINUTE.
THAT'S NOT YOUR EIGHTH GRADE
DANCE FRUIT PUNCH.
SO WE'RE USING BRISKET
WITH THE CAP ON?
GET 'EM READY
TO GO UNDERWATER.
ONE IMPORTANT STEP IS TO KEEP
THE MEAT AGAINST THE MEAT
AND THE FAT
AGAINST THE FAT.
IF THE FAT WERE TO BE
TOUCHING THE MEAT...
IT'S TOO HARD
TO PENETRATE...
THROUGH THE FAT
INTO THAT.
INTO THE MEAT.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
YOUR LITTLE LAB CLASS?
AND YOU HAVE TO HAVE ENOUGH
WATER TO COVER IT ALL.
YOU GOTTA SUBMERGE IT.
OKAY, LET'S PUT THESE AWAY.
AND THEY'LL CURE
IN THE COOLER UP TO FIVE DAYS
TILL THEY'RE DONE.
SO YOU ALWAYS HAVE
THESE THINGS IN ROTATION?
YOU'VE GOT ONE GOING--
COUPLE DAY, COUPLE DAY,
COUPLE DAY,
EVERYBODY'S...
TODAY, YESTERDAY,
DAY BEFORE YESTERDAY.
IT'S THAT
POPULAR OF AN ITEM
THAT YOU'RE RUNNING THIS THING
THROUGH ALL THE TIME...
TWO OR THREE DAYS
AHEAD OF TIME.
WHEN YOU'RE OUT, THEY'RE
GRUMPY. THESE ARE READY.
SO ALMOST EVERY DAY
YOU MAKE ONE?
EVERY DAY WE MAKE ONE.
RIGHT OUT HERE
IN THE PARKING LOT.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD
ARE WE SMOKIN' WITH?
JUST MAPLE.
IT'S A PELLET SMOKER.
THIS IS A PELLET SMOKER.
IT'LL PROCESS WOOD PELLETS
THEY FEED AUTOMATICALLY.
IT GIVES A NICE
CONSISTENT PRODUCT.
SO ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF?
HOUR AND A HALF.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA PULL 'EM
AND GO IN THE OVEN WITH 'EM.
250 FOR 3 HOURS.
LET 'EM COOL.
TILL THE NEXT DAY.
PULL, THERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT THAT!
ONE TO SLICE AND ONE
TO TAKE HOME AS A SOUVENIR?
YOU BET.
SO YOU'RE SEPARATING
THE CAP FROM THE FLAP.
IT'S LIKE PENNIES
FROM HEAVEN.
IF THAT'S HOW
GOOD THAT IS COLD...
YOU'RE GONNA
REALLY LIKE IT WARM.
YOU'RE READY TO ROLL.
IS THAT A SANDWICH?
1/2-POUND SANDWICHES.
SO NOW THIS
IS GONNA STEAM?
YES, SIR. THIS IS
A HIGH-POWER MICROWAVE.
THERE'S WATER IN THERE,
AND THAT CREATES OUR STEAMER.
I LIKE THAT
LITTLE TRICK.
SOME MONTREAL
JEWISH RYE BREAD.
TURN ON SMELLOVISION.
AHH, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S MADE FOR US
RIGHT HERE IN TOWN
WITH GOLD PREPARED MUSTARD,
1/2 POUND, YOU READY? ALL YOURS.
THE JOWLS,
THEY START TO...
MMM... MMM... MMM.
AS YOU CAN SEE FROM
MY SIX CONSECUTIVE BITES,
I DON'T LIKE IT.
OH, THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
SO THAT'S THE COUSIN
OF CORNED BEEF AND PASTRAMI
THAT LIVES
IN CANADA, EH?
IT'S PERFECTLY JUICY.
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
VERY TENDER.
GOT THE THING YOU LOVE
ABOUT CORNED BEEF
AND THE THINGS
YOU LOVE ABOUT PASTRAMI--
A LITTLE SMOKE FROM
THE PASTRAMI,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE BRINE
FROM THE CORNED BEEF.
AND THE SECRET, OF COURSE--
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSTARD.
OH, YEAH,
GETTING FULL ALREADY.
I ONLY ATE HALF OF IT.
I WOULDN'T EVEN HAVE
ANYTHING ELSE ON THE MENU.
I THOUGHT OF THAT.
BUT IT IS BREWBURGERS...
PERFECT BURGER.
DONE ALL KINDS OF WAYS.
IT'S NOT A CHEESEBURGER. IT'S
A BLUE CHEESE AND BISON BURGER.
I'M HAVING
THE BLUE JAY BURGER.
IT'S MUSHROOMS AND BLUE CHEESE
AND CRISPY FRIED ONIONS.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS BEEF, MIX
IT WITH HAND-SLICED PORTOBELLOS,
AND WE'RE GONNA
FIX YOU A BURGER.
WOW.
CRISPY MUSHROOM
ON THE OUTSIDE.
AND NICE SUCCULENT
SOFT MUSHROOM IN THE MIDDLE.
THERE YOU GO.
REALLY NICE BURGER.
FETA HAVARTI.
AND THERE'S
A TUNA BURGER...
IT'S GOOD.
A SALMON BURGER...
TWO OF EVERYTHING.
FRESH GUACAMOLE,
HAND-CUT RINGS...
THEY'RE AMAZING.
AND HOMEMADE SOUP.
I FIND IT
TO BE REALLY UNIQUE.
YOU MAKE
HANDMADE FOOD.
YOU GOT GUYS THAT WENT
TO CHEF SCHOOL,
SO WE CREATE IT
A STEP ABOVE.
SO YOU MAKE FRESH PESTO FOR
A SALAD THAT COMES AS A SIDE?
CORRECT.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL.
AND IT'S ALL BEING
SERVED UP AT A SPORTS BAR.
YOU DON'T EXPECT
TO GET THIS TYPE OF FOOD.
TWO ORDERS OF NACHOS.
CAJUN NACHOS, WHICH
HAVE ALLIGATOR IN THEM.
THEY'RE EXCELLENT.
YOU JUST DON'T FIND GOOD
ALLIGATOR EVERY DAY,
NOW DO YA?
NOT IN OMAHA.
ALLIGATOR BITES
ARE AWESOME.
NOW IS
THIS TENDERLOIN?
1-FOOT SECTION
OF THE TAIL--
SUPPOSEDLY THE LEAST TOUGHEST
PART OF THE ALLIGATOR.
THEN THIS BREADING
WE MAKE HOMEMADE, TOO.
IT'S GOT SALT AND PEPPER
AND PAPRIKA,
AND WE PUT A LITTLE
BAKING POWDER IN THERE...
WELL, THAT MUST...
TO GIVE IT THAT
CRISPY OUTER SHELL.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT
IN SOME BUTTERMILK.
SO YOU'RE DOING A LITTLE
WET HAND, DRY HAND HERE?
WET HAND, DRY HAND.
WE'RE GONNA FRY THIS.
AND WHAT'S
IT GET SERVED WITH?
WE'RE GONNA GIVE YA
A LITTLE GINGER SAUCE.
ALLIGATOR AND GINGER--
SOUNDS LIKE A DANCE DUET.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD--NICE
TEXTURE, FANTASTIC BATTER.
THE ALLIGATOR.
OH, THAT'S DIFFERENT.
WELL, WE GO THE EXTRA MILE
TO NOT BE LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE.
WITH ONE EXCEPTION.
WE'RE GONNA
NEED SOME CHEESE.
IT'S A BURGER
HE WAS INSPIRED TO MAKE
AFTER TRIPLE "D" DISCOVERED IT
AT A JOINT IN CALIFORNIA.
SO YOU LIKE IT SO MUCH THAT YOU
COME BACK TO YOUR OWN RESTAURANT
AND YOU PUT IT
ON THE MENU...
WHEN WE COME BACK.
TWO OLD-FASHIONED.
BREWBURGERS
IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA,
IS DOIN' THE SPORTS BAR
THING THEIR OWN WAY...
YOU DON'T EXPECT TO GET
THIS TYPE OF FOOD.
LIKE A FRENCH-CANADIAN
VERSION
OF A NEW YORK DELI
PASTRAMI SANDWICH...
MMM, THAT IS DYNAMITE.
ALLIGATOR BITES...
SO GOOD.
AND SERIOUS BURGERS--
EVEN BURIED WITH CHEESE...
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
LIKE THE ONE
WE FIRST DISCOVERED
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA, AT
A JOINT CALLED THE SQUEEZE INN.
THAT'S A SQUEEZE INN
BURGER, FOR SURE.
HA-HA!
THAT'S THE KEY.
(man) I'M GONNA THROW
A LITTLE MORE ICE ON THERE.
ALL THAT'S GONNA DO
IS GENERATE STEAM.
THROW IT ON TOP, AND THEN
YOU'RE GONNA PUT THE HOOD ON.
SEE THAT?
NOW WHAT--DOES ALL
THE CHEESE GO WITH IT?
HELL YEAH,
YOU'RE GOOD, MAN.
COMIN' OVER HOT.
PERFECT.
(woman) WELL, YOU SEE
THE CHEESE JUST HANGS OUT HERE.
WITH THE CHEESE SKIRT
AND THE WHOLE THING?
CHEESE SKIRT
AND THE WHOLE THING.
YOU'VE REALLY BEEN THERE?
I'VE REALLY BEEN THERE.
SO YOU LIKE IT SOME MUCH
THAT YOU COME BACK
TO YOUR OWN RESTAURANT
AND YOU PUT IT ON THE MENU
AND CALL IT
THE CHEESY SACRAMENTO.
IT'S WORTH THE WAIT
IN EITHER PLACE.
1/2 POUND, 80/20.
CERTIFIED ANGUS.
A LITTLE SALT, A LITTLE
PEPPER WHEN IT'S COOKING?
NO SALT, NO PEPPER.
JUST LET IT BE.
JUST LET IT
BE GOOD STUFF.
SOME OF THAT
CALIFORNIA CHEDDAR.
AND THAT'S ENOUGH CHEESE?
'CAUSE I'M TELLIN' YA...
OH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
THERE WE GO A LITTLE MORE.
NOW DO YOU DO THE WHOLE THING
WITH THROWIN' THE ICE IN THERE
AND THE WHOLE DEAL?
CAN'T AFFORD THE ICE.
NO, REALLY? ICE
IS A PREMIUM HERE?
SO A LITTLE
BIT OF WATER...
SO A LITTLE WATER.
STILL GET KINDA
THE SAME IDEA.
SHOULD WE CHECK
IT? ALMOST. YOU READY?
ALMOST THERE. SO YOU SEE
THE SKIRT'S STARTIN' TO BUILD.
SEE?
SHE READY?
SHE'S THERE.
♪♪
HUH. THAT'S
THE PROOF RIGHT THERE.
EXCELLENT SKIRT.
EXCELLENT TRIBUTE--
JUICY, SALTY, NICE BUN,
NOT OVERCOOKED, GREAT MEAT,
6 BUCKS ON WEDNESDAY.
I DON'T HAVE ANYTHING
ELSE TO SAY.
QUITE A BIT OF CHEESE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD AND DIFFERENT.
(Yves) WE WANTED TO BE
A SPECIAL PLACE FOR BURGERS.
(man) FOUR SACRAMENTOS.
WE WANTED TO HAVE A REPUTATION
FOR DOING STUFF THE RIGHT WAY.
(man) THE OLD-FASHIONED
WITH SWISS.
IT'S DEFINITELY
MORE THAN I EXPECTED.
YOU WANT THIS
NACHO WORKIN'?
FROM ALLIGATOR
TO THE CANADIAN
SMOKED-MEAT SANDWICH.
I THINK WHEN PEOPLE
THINK THEY COME TO OMAHA
THEY'RE GETTIN'
STEAK AND POTATOES...
RIGHT.
AND GRANTED, THIS MAY
BE MEAT AND POTATOES,
BUT IT'S SURE
ON A DIFFERENT SCALE.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE SIDES
ON THAT SWISS?
(Guy) WILL THE MENU
CONTINUE TO EVOLVE?
(Yves) IT'LL
ALWAYS CHANGE.
WHY?
I LIKE TO TRAVEL AND FIND
SOMETHING NEW SOMEWHERE,
MAYBE SACRAMENTO,
MAYBE MONTREAL--OH, BEEN THERE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE "D"--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'M FEELIN' COMFORTABLE
UP AT THIS HEIGHT.
DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH-
DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH-DUH!
(laughter)
(makes exploding noises)