I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
YOU WANT
TO KEEP ON EATING.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I'M LOVIN' IT.
BIG FLAVOR.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
HERE WE GO.
IN BALTIMORE...
OH.
TONS OF CHOICES.
PIZZA GONE WILD.
I LOVE MAC AND CHEESE.
SPAM PIZZA.
I'M FREAKIN' OUT.
I'M EATING SPAM.
YOU WANT SOME FRIES WITH THAT?
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
I'M SO HAPPY.
A TASTE OF HAVANA...
MMM!
AT A LITTLE JOINT
DOING BIG CUBAN FLAVOR.
CREOLE SAUCE
SURROUNDED BY DELICIOUSNESS.
THAT'S TOO LEGIT.
AND IN MISSISSIPPI...
OH, YOU SEE HOW THE FLAVORS
ARE COMING TOGETHER?
A SMOKIN' SHACK...
LAST PAN OF RIBS.
THAT'S DOING CREOLE
AND CAJUN...
BIG FLAVOR.
IT'S SO GOOD.
DARWELL'S HAS THE TASTE
OF THE SOUTH.
COMPLETE WITH A FLOOR SHOW.
NEW CUSTOMERS.
THIS IS WHAT YOU'RE GONNA
GROW UP TO BE LIKE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M CRUISING AROUND
FELLS POINT
HERE IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND,
AND I'M KIND OF STARTING
TO FEEL LIKE PIZZA.
I'VE BEEN TOLD
I'VE GOT TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
CALLED BRICK OVEN PIZZA,
WHERE THEY'RE DOING A WOOD-FIRE
PIZZA TOTALLY THEIR OWN WAY.
I MEAN, LOOK AT WHAT
THEY'RE PUTTING ON TOP.
CAN YOU SAY FRENCH FRIES?
HOW ABOUT SOY CHEESE?
OR MAYBE SOME SPAM.
SPAM PIZZA.
IT TASTES LIKE BUTTER.
I'VE GOT TO SAY,
IT'S PRETTY TASTY.
DON'T WANT SPAM?
HOW ABOUT MAC AND CHEESE?
I'M LOVIN' IT.
NOW THEY GOT ALL THE BASICS...
HAVE THE CHEESE PIZZA,
OR MAYBE A PEPPERONI.
BUT THAT'S ONLY THE BEGINNING.
TONS OF CHOICES.
AND OPEN-FACED
CHEESESTEAK?
WITH FRENCH FRIES.
MARINATED PESTO CHICKEN PIZZA.
I LIKE
THE CREATIVITY PART OF IT.
AND FOR MIKE BECKNER
AND WIFE DEBRA ROMANO...
HERE WE GO.
DOING THIS,
EVEN 16 HOURS A DAY...
PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
IS JUST MORE FUN
THAN THEIR OLD JOBS IN SALES.
I CAN PRETTY MUCH DO
WHAT I WANT TO.
LIKE PESTO WITH CHICKEN,
HAWAIIAN WITH PINEAPPLE...
I LOVE IT.
BUT THAT'S JUST A START.
IT'S LIKE PUTTING SPAM
ON A PIZZA.
DON'T TELL ME I CAN'T
DO IT, 'CAUSE I CAN DO IT.
YOU READY?
MMM. GREAT.
I'M FREAKIN' OUT.
I'M EATING SPAM.
IT'S GOOD, ISN'T IT?
IT'S REALLY GREAT.
THE ONIONS, THE TOMATOES,
THE RANCH DRESSING--
IT'S QUITE NICE.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
AND UNDERNEATH IT ALL...
THE CRUST IS CRISP.
EVERY GOOD PIZZA'S
GOT TO HAVE THIS.
NICE HOOK, CAPTAIN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
FIVE PITCHERS OF WHITE FLOUR.
NOW HOW MANY TIMES WILL
YOU MAKE DOUGH IN A DAY?
ABOUT TEN TIMES.
IN A DAY.
WOW.
SO WE'LL DO ONE
AND A HALF OF THE WHEAT.
TICKLE THE TASTE BUDS
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF A TEXTURE DIFFERENCE?
1/4 CUP OF SALT.
HERE'S THE YEAST.
SO WE'LL LET THIS MIX.
POUR THE WATER.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
AND LUKE WARM WATER.
TO ACTIVATE THE YEAST.
15-MINUTE DANCE AND THEN
LET IT COME OUT AND PROOF.
YEP.
WHAT SIZE BALLS
DO YOU MAKE?
I DO A 4 OUNCE,
8 OUNCE,
22 OUNCE--
22 OUNCE?
YOU FOLD THEM OVER
AND IN.
FOLD 'EM IN.
AND PINCH AND TWIST.
YOU'VE DONE
THIS BEFORE, HUH?
YEAH.
AND ONCE IT'S BAKED...
THE CRUST,
I GOT TO TELL YOU--
THAT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE
THINGS ON THE BOTTOM IT,
'CAUSE IT'S GOT THAT
NICE REALLY GOOD CHEW TO IT.
THE CRUST IS ORIGINAL, CRUNCHY,
ALWAYS JUST DONE PERFECTLY.
AND ON TOP OF THAT CRUST...
WE HAVE CUSTOMERS
DOWN HERE
WHO ARE WILLING TO TRY
A LOT OF DIFFERENT THINGS.
I WOULD NEVER THINK TO HAVE
FRENCH FRIES ON A PIZZA.
BUT MIKE WOULD.
STEAK AND POTATO PIZZA.
DO YOU MAKE THIS
EVERY TIME FROM SCRATCH?
YES.
THERE'S ONION,
MUSHROOMS, GREEN PEPPERS
AND A FEW
LITTLE CHERRY PEPPERS
JUST TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE SPICE.
ADD OUR CHOPPED BEEF TO IT.
NICE LITTLE AMOUNT
OF MEAT THERE.
YOU GOT TO TASTE THE MEAT.
WE'LL COOK IT TILL WE JUST GET
THE PINKNESS OUT OF THE MEAT.
DO YOU LET IT COOL BEFORE
YOU PUT IT ON THE PIZZA?
YEAH.
SO THIS IS THE FRIES,
THE MEAT.
THIS IS LIKE A GOOD
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
YEAH.
STRETCH OUT OUR DOUGH.
I LIKE MAYONNAISE
ON MY CHEESESTEAKS.
(whistles)
HOT MAYONNAISE
I CAN'T TAKE.
NOT GOOD.
SO WHAT WE'LL USE
ON THIS IS A RANCH BASE.
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE GOING
WITH THIS SO FAR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD THE STEAK
THAT WE HAD COOKED BEFORE,
AND WE NEED TO GET
THE POTATO PART,
AND WE'LL START ADDING
FRENCH FRIES.
ADD SOME AMERICAN CHEESE
TO IT, AND THERE WE GO.
RIGHT.
IT'S READY FOR THE OVEN.
THAT SMELLS DYNAMITE.
MMM! OH HO!
THE MEAT'S SUPER TENDER.
CHEESE IS ON POINT.
THAT'S UP THERE
WITH THE BEST.
YOU COULD TASTE
THE FRENCH FRIES A LITTLE BIT.
IT HAD A NICE MEATY
TASTE TO IT.
VERY UNIQUE-TASTING.
VERY GOOD.
BEST PIZZA IN TOWN,
HANDS DOWN.
WE CAN PICK
ANYTHING WE WANT.
I LOVE MAC AND CHEESE,
AND I LOVE PIZZA.
TOGETHER IS LIKE
THE ULTIMATE BOMB.
FOR YOUR MAC AND CHEESE,
WE NEED A LITTLE BIT
OF ALFREDO SAUCE
TO GIVE IT SOME TEXTURE.
HALF-AND-HALF TO IT,
A LITTLE GARLIC BUTTER.
LET THAT SIMMER.
YOU MAKE THIS EACH TIME
YOU NEED A PIZZA?
YES.
GET IN LINE?
GET IN LINE.
WOW.
A LITTLE BIT OF PARMESAN,
AND THAT'S OUR BASE
FOR OUR MAC AND CHEESE.
WHERE DO YOU BOIL
THE WATER FOR THE PASTA?
RIGHT HERE.
THERE'S ONLY ONE
EMPIRE STATE BUILDING,
AND ONLY ONE BURNER
HERE AT B.O.P.
NO, I'VE GOT THREE
OR FOUR OF THEM.
WHERE ARE THEY?
ON VACATION?
NO, YOU JUST CAN'T PLUG 'EM
ALL IN AT ONE TIME.
OKAY, SO YOU GOT SOME
PRECOOKED PENNE RIGATE.
ALFREDO SAUCE INTO IT,
AND WE'LL ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR CHEDDAR TO IT.
GARLIC BUTTER TO OUR CRUST
AND ADD OUR PASTA.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW HOW LONG WILL THIS
TAKE TO BAKE?
ABOUT FOUR MINUTES.
IT'S A GOOD-LOOKING CRUST.
MMM. CHEESY BREAD
WITH PASTA ON IT.
I THINK THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE KIDS MUST LOVE THIS.
OH, THEY LOVE IT.
IT'S LIKE MY TWO FAVORITE
THINGS. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT MAKES A NEW JERSEY
OR NEW YORK PIZZA
PALE BY COMPARISON.
(Guy) NO.
IT DOES.
YOU CAN DEFINITELY TELL THAT
IT'S BRICK OVEN-BAKED PIZZA.
THAT IS A DYNAMITE,
DYNAMITE PIZZA OVEN.
THIS OVEN IS 8 FEET WIDE,
8 FEET DEEP?
YES.
FROM ITALY.
AND WHAT TYPE OF WOOD
ARE WE USING?
WE'RE USING A HARD OAK.
AND THAT DECK'S
AT ABOUT 750 TODAY?
PUT YOUR HAND
IN THERE,
IF YOU CAN KEEP IT IN THERE
MORE THAN THREE SECONDS,
IT'S NOT HOT ENOUGH.
IT WILL LITERALLY COOK
IN, LIKE, FOUR MINUTES?
MM-HMM.
I CAN NOT BELIEVE HOW CRISP
THAT CRUST IS ON THAT PIZZA.
ONLY WAY TO GO.
AND WHEN
YOU'RE LOADING IT UP...
YOU CAN MAKE
YOUR OWN COMBINATION.
OVER 50 TOPPINGS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN POTATOES
AND RICOTTA CHEESE WITH SPINACH
ALL AT THE SAME TIME
ON THE PIZZA.
AN 18-INCH PIZZA WITH ALL
52 TOPPINGS FOR 175 BUCKS?
179.
GOIN' UP 4 BUCKS.
AND PEOPLE COME IN
AND SAY, "GIVE ME ALL OF IT"?
YEP.
LOTS OF BIG FLAVOR.
I DO LOVE PIZZA, SO YOU CAN
PUT ANYTHING ON A PIZZA
AND I WOULD
PROBABLY EAT IT.
I LOVE THE FACT THAT THEY
PUT SOY CHEESE ON PIZZA.
VEGETARIAN PIZZA--
I USE A VEGAN SOY CHEESE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
MORE MARINARA.
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
PUT OUR VEGGIES ON TOP
OF THE MARINARA.
BLACK OLIVES,
ARTICHOKE HEARTS, MUSHROOMS.
BIG SELLER, THIS ONE?
YEAH.
BROCCOLI, A LITTLE ONION,
A COUPLE LITTLE CAPERS.
OH, THAT'S A NICE
LITTLE KICKER.
SOY CHEESE.
THE SOY CHEESE
SCARES ME A BIT.
OH, IT'S GOOD.
OH, THAT IS GOOD.
KIND OF A FUNKY FLAVOR
TO IT. I LIKE IT.
THIS COOKS
THE SAME AMOUNT OF TIME?
ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
3 MINUTES? NO WONDER
YOU CAN COOK 120 PIZZAS
AND ONLY COME IN
AT 5:00 IN THE MORNING.
MMM. THERE'S SO MUCH FLAVOR
GOING ON IN THAT MARINARA.
THE CHEESE HAS GOT
A NICE TANG TO IT,
BUT IT REALLY COMPLEMENTS WELL.
IT'S NICE. IT'S CREAMY.
BUT THE CAPERS ARE WHAT
MAKE IT. I LOVE IT.
DUDE, YOU KILLIN' THIS.
THANK YOU.
LOOK IT. I ALMOST ATE
A WHOLE PIECE.
IT BLENDS REALLY WELL.
ALL THE VEGETABLES MIX
TOGETHER REALLY GOOD.
THE CAPERS--THEY ADD ANOTHER
LEVEL OF FLAVOR TO IT.
THEY'VE MADE IT
INTO AN ART.
(woman) TONS OF CHOICES.
YOU'LL NEVER GET BORED.
BEST PIZZA IN TOWN BY FAR.
SICILIAN SPECIAL.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING UNIQUE AND DIFFERENT.
IT'S THE BEST THING EVER.
IF I'M IN FELLS POINT,
I'LL BE IN HERE,
AND I'M COMING
FOR A 52.
YOU GOT IT.
I JUST NEED
174 MORE BUCKS.
9.
IT JUST CONTINUES
TO GO UP.
UP NEXT...
YOU GOT TO HAVE IT.
WE'RE HEADING NORTH
TO MINNESOTA FOR WHAT ELSE?
SANDWICH CUBANO.
CUBAN COOKIN'.
IT'S LIKE BEING
BACK IN MIAMI.
I COULD EAT THAT
EVERY DAY.
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
I'M ALWAYS LOOKING FOR
HERE ON TRIPLE "D"--
THOSE SMALL LITTLE JOINTS
THAT MAKE YOU STOP
AND SAY, "WHAT IN THE HECK?"
LIKE THIS SMALL
TROPICAL-LOOKING DIVE
HERE IN SOUTH MINNEAPOLIS.
NOW IT'S A SMALL JOINT,
BUT PEOPLE SAY
VICTOR'S 1959 CAFé
IS PACKED WITH BIG FLAVOR.
THE FLAVORS ARE UNIQUE...
MMM... AND DIVINE.
IT'S LIKE
BEING BACK IN MIAMI.
OR HAVANA.
GOOD SAUCE.
FROM LIME-
AND-GARLIC-MARINATED PORK...
IF YOU'RE A PORK FAN,
YOU GOT TO HAVE IT.
THE STEAK WITH FRIED GREEN
PLANTAINS CALLED TOSTONE
AND CLASSIC CUBAN SANDWICHES.
CUBAN HASH?
ALL THIS COOKED BY A WOMAN...
OPA!
WHOSE BACKGROUND IS GREEK.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE CUBAN
TO COOK CUBAN FOOD,
BUT IT'S REALLY GREAT
IF YOU CAN LEARN FROM A CUBAN.
SANDWICH CUBANO.
THAT'S WHAT NIKI STAVROU DID
WHEN SHE OPENED THIS JOINT
WITH HER THEN-HUSBAND
NINE YEARS AGO.
HE'S FROM CUBA.
THE RECIPES
THAT I LEARNED FROM HIM
ARE AUTHENTIC CUBAN RECIPES,
AND IT'S BEEN IMPORTANT
THAT I KEEP IT THAT WAY.
THIS IS WHAT I COME FOR.
THE RANCHERO CUBANO
WITH THE BEANS AND PLANTAINS--
IT'S A REALLY GOOD
ASSORTMENT OF FLAVORS.
DO YOU RECOMMEND
THE PICADILLO?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S GOT A GOOD
FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S A VERY A TRADITIONAL,
AUTHENTIC CUBAN DISH.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE BEEF.
I'M JUST GONNA LET IT START
BROWNING FOR A MINUTE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT, PEPPER.
SO WE'RE ALL BROWNED UP.
NOW WHO ELSE
JUMPS IN THE POOL?
THE CREOLE SAUCE.
THE CREOLE SAUCE
IN THE CUBAN FOOD?
YEAH.
THAT'S PART OF THE SPANISH
INFLUENCE IN CUBA.
WHAT YOU GOT--THE OREGANO
AND THE GARLIC
AND THE PEPPERS
AND THE TOMATO SAUCE.
EXACTLY.
GREEN STUFFED OLIVES.
SOMETIMES CALLED
SPANISH OLIVES
WITH THE LITTLE
PIMENTOS INSIDE.
THAT ADDS A LITTLE BIT
OF SALTINESS, ALSO.
MY MOUTH'S WATERING.
RAISINS.
NICE LITTLE
SWEETNESS THERE.
A LITTLE BIT MORE SALT
IN THE CAPERS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GIVE
SOME SPICE--OREGANO.
CUMIN AND OREGANO.
OF COURSE.
SOME GOOD FRIENDS
OF THE CUBAN FOOD.
GARLIC.
WE LOVE GARLIC.
OH.
PLENTY OF GARLIC
IN CUBAN COOKING.
SWEET BAY LEAVES. GIVE IT
A LITTLE STIR NOW.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME POTATOES.
OH.
SMELLS KILLER.
TASTES EVEN BETTER.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY IT.
SO LET IT SIMMER
ABOUT 15 MINUTES?
YEAH.
WE SERVE IT WITH RICE
AND BEANS
AND SWEET PLANTAINS.
MMM.
MMM!
THAT IS AWESOME.
GOOD. I'M GLAD
YOU LIKE IT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF SALTINESS
FROM THE CAPER
THAT WAS RIGHT THERE.
SWEETNESS OF THE RAISIN
AND SOME OF THE CREAMINESS
OF THE BEANS.
OH. IT'S CAN IT GET TO
THE FACE WITHOUT FALLING?
MMM.
I COULD EAT THAT
EVERY DAY.
IT IS REALLY SPICY
AND FLAVORFUL.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT
THE OLIVES ARE WHOLE.
YOU REALLY GET
THE OLIVE FLAVOR.
I'VE HAD EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU,
AND THEY'RE ALL WONDERFUL.
WHO HAD THE TOSTONES?
AND REMEMBER,
THIS ISN'T MIAMI.
THIS IS THE PLACE IN MINNESOTA
YOU CAN GET REAL CUBAN COFFEE,
REAL ROPA VIEJA.
AND YOU'RE CUBAN.
YEAH.
LET ME SEE THE TATTOO.
YEAH, MAYBE HE'S CUBAN.
THAT OR HE'S A REAL
BIG FAN.
WHEN YOU WALK IN,
YOU'RE TOTALLY TRANSPORTED.
TO A CUBAN JOINT...
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S BECOME A FAVORITE
MINNESOTA HANGOUT...
THIS IS IT.
FOR EVERYTHING FROM STRIP STEAK
WITH LIME JUICE AND ONIONS
TO A CLASSIC CUBAN SANDWICH...
IT'S AMAZING.
THAT STARTS
WITH A WHOLE PORK LOIN.
LIME JUICE, OREGANO,
GARLIC, A LITTLE VINEGAR,
SALT, PEPPER--YOU'VE GOT
YOUR BASICS RIGHT THERE.
YEAH.
PUT A LID ON IT?
YEP, AND COOK IT
FOR FOUR HOURS,
BUT FOR THE LAST 30 MINUTES,
YOU TAKE THE LID OFF.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
THAT THAT NEEDS SANDWICH.
WE'RE GONNA TRANSFER IT TO
THIS PAN FOR THE SHREDDING.
JUST HURRY UP, WOULD YOU?
LOOK AT THAT.
SO LET'S MAKE A SANDWICH.
IT'S A BIG SANDWICH.
IT'S A HEARTY SANDWICH, TOO.
MUSTARD, SWISS CHEESE,
PICKLES.
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S HUMOROUS HAM.
THAT IS A HUNK
A SLICE OF HAM.
THIS IS GONNA BE,
LIKE, A 4-POUNDER.
PULLED PORK.
THAT'S PROBABLY ENOUGH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
UNLESS YOU WANT IT
A LITTLE BIT BIGGER.
YEAH, MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
ALL THE JUICE.
I'M GONNA PUT
IT BACK HERE,
'CAUSE THAT'S THE HOTTEST
PART OF THE GRILL, AND THEN...
(Guy) FLIP IT OVER?
YEP.
GOOD. NOW...
DON'T HAVE TO
ASK ME TWICE.
MMM. I THINK IT'S ABOUT
AS LEGIT AS THEY COME.
SUPER JUICY.
PICKLE FITS
IN THERE GREAT,
BUT THE BIG SLICE OF HAM--
WHAT A GIVEN.
OUT OF THE 50
THAT I'VE HAD,
THAT IS IN
THE TOP 5%.
IT'S MEATY, AND YOU CAN GET
FULL ON JUST THE SANDWICH.
I LIKE THE CUBAN FLAVOR
TO EVERYTHING.
CUBAN COOKING IS REALLY SIMPLE,
BUT IT'S JUST SO DELICIOUS.
(Guy) REAL FLAVORFUL.
ROPA VIEJA.
"ROPA VIEJA"--DO YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS?
OLD CLOTHES!
OLD CLOTHES.
AHH.
(man) FLANK STEAK
AND CREOLE SAUCE
SURROUNDED BY DELICIOUSNESS.
SO I'VE GOT FLANK STEAK.
OKAY, SO WE'VE GOT
A LITTLE FLANK.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME WATER,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT, CUMIN.
SOME BAY LEAVES.
SO WE LET THAT
SIT THERE AND SIMMER
ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
TILL IT'S READY
TO TAKE OUT.
THERE WE GO.
OKAY. LOOK AT HOW
IT JUST SHREDS.
JUST SHREDS APART.
NOW THAT IS A PILE!
IT IS.
OH.
YEAH, BABY.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE RED PEPPERS,
YELLOW PEPPERS
AND GREEN PEPPERS.
THANK YOU, SIR.
A LITTLE ONIONS.
SO IF IT'S NOT ENOUGH
THAT THIS MEAT HAS BEEN
LIGHTLY SEASONED
AND SIMMERED AND SHREDDED,
NOW IT'S GONNA BE STEAMED
BY SOME AROMATICS
OF FRESH PEPPERS AND ONIONS.
YEAH, THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
NOW I'M GONNA PUT
SOME CREOLE SAUCE IN HERE.
SO IS THIS FOR
TONIGHT'S MEAL SERVICE?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
WELL, IT'S TOO BAD
YOU'RE OUT OF THIS.
MORE GARLIC, AND I'M GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF SHERRY IN, ALSO.
THE LAST STEP--
I JUST LIKE TO SPRINKLE
SOME GREEN PEAS ON TOP
FOR A LITTLE POP OF COLOR.
AND WE'RE GONNA SERVE IT
WITH RICE
AND SWEET PLANTAINS.
HMM. THAT IS GREAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF THE RICE,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE ROPA
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE PLANTAIN.
THAT SHOULD BE A RULE
ON THE MENU.
DON'T TAKE A BITE UNLESS
YOU TAKE ALL THREE TOGETHER.
MMM. YOU GET THAT DEEP
RICH TOMATO FLAVOR
WITH THE ONIONS
AND PEPPERS,
SWEET CRUNCHY PLANTAIN
IN THE BACK.
THAT'S TOO LEGIT.
YOU REALLY CAN'T GO WRONG.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
I LOVE IT.
IF YOU LIVE WITHIN
500 MILES OF THIS JOINT,
MAKE A VACATION
OUT OF IT.
DEFINITELY UNIQUE.
I CAN'T WAIT TO DRAG
MY HUSBAND HERE.
HOW DOES IT STACK UP?
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
WELL DONE, GIRL.
THANK YOU.
WELL DONE.
WE'RE GONNA HUG
AFTER EVERY MEAL.
WELL, I'M GREEK, YOU KNOW?
I CAN'T HELP MYSELF.
NEXT STOP...
LIKE NOTHING ELSE YOU'VE HAD.
A MISSISSIPPI JOINT,
WHERE THEY'RE DOING BIG FLAVOR
THEIR OWN WAY.
I LIKE WHAT YOU GOT--
REAL FOOD, REAL PEOPLE.
OKAY, FOLKS,
LAST PAN OF RIBS.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES TO
LIVE WAS LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA,
SO YOU GOT TO KNOW
I WAS STOKED
WHEN I FOUND OUT THERE'S
A LONG BEACH, MISSISSIPPI.
NOW IF YOU FIND YOURSELF HERE,
YOU GOT TO COME CHECK OUT
THIS CRAZY SHACK--DARWELL'S.
PEOPLE AROUND HERE
SAY THAT THEY'RE TURNING OUT
SOME TOP-NOTCH FOOD.
MMM. GOOD.
LIKE NOTHING ELSE
YOU'VE HAD ANYWHERE ELSE.
BIG FLAVOR, AND YOU WANT
TO KEEP ON EATING.
DARWELL'S HAS THE TASTE
OF THE SOUTH. SO TENDER.
AND IT'S SO GOOD, I'M THINKIN'
ABOUT SPIKING MY HAIR UP.
FROM BARBECUE
TO CAJUN AND CREOLE...
IT'S JUST REAL FOOD.
SAUSAGE PLATE.
AND HAS BEEN EVER
SINCE DARWELL YEAGER--
THE LOCALS CALL HIM "D"...
AND I'VE GOT
A PRIME RIB PLATE.
OPENED THE JOINT
A FEW YEARS BACK.
I LIKE WHAT YOU GOT--
REAL FOOD, REAL PEOPLE.
OKAY, FOLKS.
AND WITH A LITTLE HELP
FROM HIS DAD,
WHO'S HARD TO MISS...
NEW CUSTOMERS.
PAPA D,
HE'S JUST PAPA D.
WE GOT SOME NATIVES HERE
AND SOME WEST COAST PEOPLE
OVER HERE.
SIT BACK AND ENJOY HIM.
THIS IS WHAT YOU'RE GONNA
GROW UP TO BE LIKE.
HOPEFULLY.
SO THAT'S YOUR DAD'S
DESIGN OUT FRONT?
THAT'S PAPA D's
DESIGN, YEAH.
AND THIS IS YOUR DOMAIN?
THIS IS MINE.
HE STARTED IN THE FOOD BIZ
AT 15
AND THEN DID SOME MOONLIGHTING
IN HIS 20s.
I WAS
A PROFESSIONAL WRESTLER.
HOLD ON.
THAT'S IT, BABY.
DID THEY THROW YOU?
I MEAN, WHAT WAS--
MAN, THEY DID ALL KIND
OF STUFF, BUT MY DAD TOLD ME,
"SON, YOU NEED
TO GET OUT OF THE RING
AND GET BACK
IN THE KITCHEN."
TO FOCUS ON WHAT HE DOES BEST.
I WAS TRAINED BY SOME OF
THE HIGHEST CHEFS IN THIS AREA
ON HOW TO PUT IT OUT
AND HOW TO MAKE IT TASTE GOOD.
THIS CREOLE GIVES ME
A GOOD BURST OF FLAVOR.
WHO MADE UP THIS RECIPE?
THIS IS MY RECIPE.
HERE WE GO. CELERY SAUTéING
IN A 1/4 POUND OF BUTTER.
WHY DID YOU BLANCH
THE BELL PEPPER?
SO IT WOULD COOK
A LITTLE FASTER.
SAUTéED ONION--
THEY'VE BEEN BLANCHED ALSO.
SAUTé YOUR VEGETABLES
TILL THEY'RE NICE AND TENDER.
CREOLE SEASONING.
THIS IS TONY CHACHERE'S.
IT'S VERY GOOD IN THIS AREA.
VERY PROUD--
EVERYBODY KNOWS TONY'S.
OLD BAY SEASONING. OLD BAY
ACCENTS THE SEAFOOD REALLY WELL.
BAY LEAVES
AND MINCED GARLIC.
OH, YOU SEE HOW THE FLAVORS
ARE COMING TOGETHER
AND EVERYTHING'S STARTING
TO MARRY IN THERE?
WE GOT ONE IMPORTANT STEP
THAT WE'VE GOT TO MAKE--
THE SMOKED SAUSAGES.
THEY'VE GOT TO GO
IN WITH THE BUTTER.
TO BRING THAT FAT
OUT OF THAT SAUSAGE,
YOU WANT
TO RENDER THAT DOWN.
RENDER FAT.
FLOUR'S GOING DOWN.
YEP, FLOUR'S--
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE ROUX
RIGHT INSIDE OF THAT.
NOW I NEED
THE SHRIMP STOCK.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T SOUS-CHEF
FOR MANY, ALL RIGHT?
NOW DID YOU MAKE
THIS SHRIMP STOCK YOURSELF?
YES, I DID.
ABOUT 200 POUNDS OF SHRIMP
BOILS DOWN TO BE
ABOUT A GALLON.
OH.
TOMATO SAUCE,
AND WE'RE GONNA LET THIS COOK
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR.
WE'RE ALL TIGHTENED UP?
LOOKIN' GREAT.
I ACTUALLY HEAT THE SHRIMP
TO ORDER.
IF I HAVE PREACHED ONE THING,
THAT WOULD BE IT,
IS THAT SEAFOOD OVERCOOKS,
AND WHEN PEOPLE GO
AND MAKE THESE BIG VATS
OF GUMBOS OR STEWS,
THEN THEY LEAVE EVERYTHING IN
THERE, ALL IT DOES IS JUST...
MUSH.
IT EITHER TURNS TO MUSH
OR TURNS INTO BBs.
RUBBER.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT.
IT'S SERVED OVER A LIGHT
LONG-GRAIN BASMATI RICE.
(whistles)
THIS IS SOUTHERN
CREOLE COOKING
WITH A LITTLE INFLUENCE
OF BASMATI RICE?
IT HOLDS THE SAUCES,
AND IT REALLY MAKES
FOR A NICE PRESENTATION.
MMM. THIS IS FANTASTIC.
THE SHRIMP
IS REALLY NICE AND TENDER.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS ABOUT
THIS IS THE BASMATI RICE.
IT'S A NICE FLAVORFUL RICE.
IT'S LIGHT.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT SAUSAGE IS DYNAMITE.
WE EAT OVER IN NEW ORLEANS QUITE
A BIT, BUT THIS IS JUST AS GOOD.
AND THE SHRIMP ARE REALLY FRESH
AND VERY TASTY.
AND THEY'RE SERVING THEM
BLACKENED, TOO,
IN DARWELL'S TAKE
ON A LOUISIANA FAVORITE...
THE éTOUFFéE.
WITH D's OWN BLACKENING SPICE.
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT,
YOU JUST KNOW
YOU'RE HAVING SOMETHING GOOD.
WE GOT PAPRIKA.
WHICH IS THE PREDOMINANT.
THREE TO ONE TO EVERYTHING.
BUT YOU GOT CAYENNE PEPPER.
THAT'S THE SUPER SPICE.
THAT'S THE HEAT?
YOU GOT OREGANO.
YOU GOT THYME.
OOH.
BLACK PEPPER,
GARLIC POWDER--
THE HOLY FAVORITE SPICE
OF ALL SOUTHERN--
OF ALL SPICES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
BLEND THAT UP.
YOU CAN MAKE YOUR
OWN BLACKENING SPICE.
AND YOU CAN
ALSO ADJUST THE SPICE
TO TASTE THE WAY
YOU LIKE IT TO TASTE.
MM-HMM.
AND I'VE KEPT THE SPICE
BACKED OUT OF THE éTOUFFéE
A LITTLE BIT.
LET THE SHRIMP CARRY IT.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. REALLY NICE.
I DON'T BELIEVE
THAT THE BLACKENING
HAS TO BE SO SPICY HOT
THAT YOU CAN'T ENJOY IT.
BLACKEN MEANS FLAVORFUL.
IT'S A GREAT BLEND.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
BANG.
ALL OF HIS FOOD IS GREAT.
NEW ORLEANS-STYLE
COOKING FLAVORS,
BARBECUE
THAT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
LAST PAN OF RIBS.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
THE PULLED PORK?
PULLED PORK.
IT'S REAL GOOD.
JUST 1 OF 18 SANDWICHES,
FROM SMOKED SAUSAGE
TO SERIOUS BURGERS.
IT'S SUPERGOOD.
WHAT DO YOU GET?
I GET THE PRIME RIB
SANDWICH. MM-HMM.
PRIME?
PRIME.
COME ON.
DADDY TAUGHT ME
IF YOU CAN'T GO
TOP-OF-THE-LINE,
DON'T GO AT ALL.
SO WE'RE GONNA COMPLETELY DRENCH
THE RIB WITH THE SOY SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA RUB HER DOWN WITH
SOME GOOD OLD MINCED GARLIC.
WE GOT THE TONY CHACHERE'S
GOING ON HERE.
SO YOU LOVE
THAT TONY SEASONING?
OH, WE LOVE IT.
BLACK PEPPER.
POP THE ONIONS IN THERE.
THIS IS GONNA GO
IN THE OVEN, 350 DEGREES
FOR ABOUT
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS REST.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SLICE IT,
'CAUSE YOU CAN'T SLICE IT HOT.
WHAT IS THAT OVER THERE?
IS THAT AN EXTRA SPOON?
OH! WHAT THE--
I WANT TO JUST LOOK
AT HOW THIN THAT IS.
IT'S SO THIN,
IT'S HARD TO KEEP IT TOGETHER
AFTER IT COMES OFF THE SLICER.
YOU DON'T NEED TO DO
ANYTHING TO THIS.
BUT HE'S GONNA.
I'M GONNA START OUT
BY LETTING IT
GET THE JUICES
KNOCKED OUT OF IT.
I GOT THE ONIONS
AND MUSHROOMS HERE.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTé THEM WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF AU JUS,
THAT DARWELL'S MAGIC
AU JUS THAT WE GOT GOIN' ON.
THEM BABIES GONNA TURN OUT
BUTTER TENDER.
YOU'RE KILLING ME
RIGHT NOW,
'CAUSE I WANT IT
MEDIUM-RARE.
HERE IT COMES.
GOT A PRIME RIB HOME
SET UP FOR ME RIGHT HERE.
YOU GOT TO GET
THE DIP IN THERE.
MMM.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE
A BIRTHDAY CAKE
MADE OUT OF THAT.
A BIG 16-LAYER BIRTHDAY CAKE
MADE OUT OF THIS.
THAT IS AWESOME, DUDE.
MMM!
IT'S ONE OF THESE THAT YOU EAT
AND EVERYTHING
RUNS DOWN YOUR HAND.
IT'S JUST MESSY
AND GOOD.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
JUST A GREAT SOUTHERN FEEL
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF A TWIST.
LIKE THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC
DONE THE DARWELL'S WAY...
(Darwell) WE'RE JUST GONNA
DUMP THAT RIGHT IN THERE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
ALL I NEED
IS A BIGGER SHOVEL.
WE'RE ORIGINAL
DARWELL-IANS.
DARWELL-IANS?
AT DARWELL'S CAFé
IN LONG BEACH, MISSISSIPPI...
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THEY'RE PACKING IN
THE LOCALS...
MMM.
WITH BIG FLAVOR...
HEY, SON!
SERVED BY A FATHER AND SON
DOING THINGS THEIR OWN WAY.
THIS CAN BE SERVED ANY TIME
OF THE DAY YOU WANT IT.
GRITS WITH TASSO.
TASSO IS A SPICY HAM.
SPICY SMOKED HAM.
START WITH THE HOT BOILING
WATER. A LITTLE SALT ADDED.
GOT IT.
WE GOT THE GRITS.
DUMP 'EM RIGHT IN,
GIVE 'EM A QUICK STIR,
AND WE'RE GONNA GO
TO ABOUT A 20- TO 30-MINUTE
SIMMER TIME ON THIS.
GOTTEN TO THE CONSISTENCY
THAT I LIKE TO SERVE MY GRITS.
SOME PEOPLE LIKE 'EM
A LITTLE THICKER.
A LITTLE THINNER.
I LIKE 'EM TO HAVE A LITTLE
BIT OF RUN TO 'EM.
THERE YOU GO.
I DON'T NECESSARILY WANT TO
STAND MY SPOON UP IN IT.
NO, IT'LL FALL OVER.
AND OVER IN THIS OTHER SKILLET
THAT I'VE GOT PREHEATING,
SOME WHOLE BUTTER.
WELL, THE DAIRY BUSINESS DOES
GOOD AROUND YOUR RESTAURANT.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE THIS
BUTTER MELTING DOWN HERE,
AND NOW WE NEED
THAT WONDERFUL TASSO.
YOU CAN'T PASS-O
ON THE TASSO.
AND NOW HERE'S THE THING.
THERE'S NO SET AMOUNT
WE'RE USING HERE.
IF YOU LIKE A LOT OF TASSO
IN GRITS, SAUTé A LOT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A NICE
LITTLE 1/2 POUND IN HERE.
GET THAT NICE AND SAUTéING
SO WE GET THE FLAVOR
OUT OF THE TASSO.
FRESH CHOPPED GREEN ONIONS
AND NICE SHARP,
SHREDDED CHEDDAR CHEESE.
INTO THE GRITS.
GIVE THIS A GOOD STIR.
WE GOT THE GRITS. WE GOT
THE CHEDDAR CHEESE GOIN'.
WE GOT
THE NICE SAUTé MIXTURE,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA DUMP
THAT RIGHT IN THERE.
NOW YOU SEE HOW EVERYTHING'S
STARTING TO COME TOGETHER HERE?
GOOD STUFF. GOOD STUFF.
I'M TELLING YOU, JUST WAIT.
GET READY, GUY.
GET READY.
MMM.
MMM! WOW, THAT'S NICE.
EAT THAT WITH SWEET TEA,
AND YOU GOT IT
ALL TOGETHER, BABY.
NOT SALTY. A LITTLE SPICY
OUT OF THE TASSO.
THAT CHEDDAR CHEESE--
NOT OVERPOWERING.
THE RIGHT CONSISTENCY.
I COULD PUT
THAT POT AWAY EASILY.
AND IT'S GOT A REAL SMOOTH
SOUTHERN FLAVOR.
AND THE TASSO'S NICE AND SPICY,
WHICH IS A NICE CONTRAST
TO THE CREAMINESS
OF THE GRITS.
IF YOU GO TO DARWELL'S,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE A GOOD
MEAL--CONSISTENTLY GOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A LOT OF FUN,
AND YOU'LL BE FULL
WHEN YOU LEAVE.
(woman) BIG FLAVORS--
FOOD THAT CAN STAND ON ITS OWN,
AND DARWELL'S MANAGES IT.
YOU GOT A LOT TO BE
PROUD OF. IT'S GREAT GOOD.
GOT A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT
OF COMMUNITY TO IT.
I MEAN, EVERYBODY
KNOWS EVERYBODY.
GOOD SEEIN' YA, D.
WHEN YOU GO TO A THEME PARK,
YOU HAVE YOUR CHARACTERS...
WE ARE THE CHARACTERS.
THEY'RE JUST
WITHOUT THE FUR.
WELL, NOT ALL OF US.
WELL...
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OKAY, SO YOU REALLY
WERE A PRO WRESTLER?
I WAS A PRO WRESTLER.
THAT'S ME, BABY.
THEY CALLED ME
"THE WIZARD," GUY.
THAT WAS THE WIZARD.
READY?
OH, I DIDN'T GET TO STAMP--
I STEPPED ON YOUR FOOT.
READY? ONE MORE TIME.