HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
IT'S BEEN AROUND
FOR YEARS AND YEARS.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
RETURN TO ROUTE 66
IN FLAGSTAFF, ARIZONA...
DELICIOUS.
MEXICAN COOKING...
WOW, THAT'S HOT.
THAT'S PRETTY AWESOME.
YEAH, IT IS.
ARIZONA-STYLE.
THIS IS A NAVAJO TACO.
AND EVERYONE'S DIVIN' IN
IN ALBUQUERQUE...
IT'S CLASSIC DINER FOOD,
BUT IT'S UPSCALE.
A DINER IN
AN OLD GAS STATION...
IT'S UNIQUE. IT'S INTERESTING,
AND IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
AND THIS...
(man) I GOT HOT FOOD
READY TO GO.
IS HOW THEY'RE FILLIN' UP.
YOU KNOW THAT SAYING,
"GET YOUR KICKS ON ROUTE 66"?
AND IN WILLOWBROOK, ILLINOIS...
TWO CHICKEN DINNERS.
THEY'RE FAMOUS FOR THEIR
CHICKEN, AND I LOVE IT.
A TON OF FRIED CHICKEN
A WEEK...
I LOVE THE BREADING.
IT'S VERY LIGHT
AND FRESH.
DONE THE SAME WAY
FOR SO LONG...
FOR YEARS AND YEARS...
IT'S IN A ROUTE 66
HALL OF FAME.
SUPER-TINY FLAKY
FALL-APARTY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D,"
YOU GOTTA LOVE A ROAD TRIP,
AND THERE'S NOTHING BETTER
THAN THE ROUTE 66 TOUR.
THIS TIME WE'RE STARTING
IN FLAGSTAFF, ARIZONA,
AT A PLACE CALLED SALSA BRAVA
WHERE THIS DUDE'S SCRATCH-MAKING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
ORDER UP.
TEQUILA POBLANO, PLEASE.
MMM. VERY GOOD.
BLACKENED SALMON TACOS.
THIS IS THE BEST MEXICAN
RESTAURANT IN FLAGSTAFF.
YOU'VE GOT YOUR GUACAMOLE.
WE DO IT BY HAND, MAN.
THE WAY ARIZONA NATIVE
JOHN CONLEY
HAS BEEN ROLLIN' FOR YEARS.
ORDER UP, PLEASE.
WHEN I WAS 21 YEARS OLD,
I DECIDED TO DROP OUT OF SCHOOL
AND OPEN MY OWN
LITTLE TACORIA.
SO WAS MEXICAN
THE FIRST CHOICE?
YOU KNOW, IT WAS.
GREEN, PLEASE.
I LOVE THE CULTURE. I LOVE
THE PEOPLE. I LOVE THE FOOD.
AND FOLKS AROUND HERE LOVE
THE WAY HE'S MAKING THE FOOD
FROM CLASSICS LIKE BURRITOS
TO SOMETHING CALLED
A MAUI TACO WITH PINEAPPLE
TO A SOUTHWESTERN FAVORITE--
SOPAPILLA.
STUFFED SOPAPILLA.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A DOUGH THAT'S
GONNA BE USED IN THE SOPAPILLA.
CORRECT.
WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE FLOUR IN.
IS THIS A PRECISE
MEASURING TECHNIQUE EVENT?
WE'RE JUST EYEBALLING THIS.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE SALT IN THERE,
A LITTLE BAKING POWDER.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT ALL UP
AND KIND IF INCORPORATE IT.
HIT ME WITH SOME WATER.
WE'RE GONNA WORK THIS AROUND
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
THE DOUGH'S A LITTLE BIT TACKY.
WE COVER IT.
AN HOUR AND A HALF LATER
WE'RE READY TO WORK WITH IT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR MARINATED CHICKEN...
FOR THE SOPAPILLA.
STUFFED SOPAPILLA.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH LEMON-LIME SODA.
NOW CARBONATION,
NO CARBONATION--DOES IT MATTER?
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THIS IS COOL WATER,
FRESH LIME JUICE,
RED WINE VINEGAR,
ABOUT A CUP AND A HALF.
THAT'S GOOD.
SAME WITH THE SOY.
HOW MUCH ON THE PEPPER?
ABOUT A QUARTER OF A CUP.
A LITTLE MORE.
A LITTLE MORE
THAN QUARTER OF A CUP.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER?
YEAH.
HOW MUCH?
QUARTER CUP.
A LITTLE MORE. THERE WE GO.
I LIKE THE COACHING.
GARLIC.
WHISK-Y, WHISK-Y?
THIS GOES RIGHT ON TOP
OF THE CHICKEN.
LOOK HOW THE CHICKEN
KIND OF HOOKS UP TOGETHER
AND DOESN'T LET THE MARINADE
PERMEATE INTO THAT,
SO HE'S GOTTA MOVE IT AROUND
A LITTLE BIT
IF HE WANTS TO GET THAT
MARINATION ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
WE'RE GONNA COVER THIS,
LET IT SIT
FOR 24 HOURS.
AND THEN LATER
WE'LL GRILL IT?
YEP.
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
IT SMELLS DYNAMITE.
SO WE GRILL IT, FINISH IT
IN THE OVEN, CHOP IT UP,
AND IT'S GONNA
GO IN SOPAPILLA.
STUFFED SOPAPILLA.
OKAY,
THIS IS OUR DOUGH.
WE TAKE ABOUT A 4-OUNCE BALL,
JUST LIKE THIS.
ROLL IT THROUGH
LIKE PIZZA DOUGH. GOT IT.
YEP.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
EACH TIME
THERE'S AN ORDER.
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
YOU CANNOT MAKE THIS
AHEAD OF TIME.
I'M SORRY.
SOPAPILLA OR SOPA FOOTBALL?
HOW MANY DOES THIS MAKE?
IT JUST MAKES ONE.
IT'S ABOUT AS BIG AS YOUR HEAD.
A LITTLE BIT OF BEANS...
NOW YOU GOTTA MOVE FAST, BECAUSE
THAT HEAT WILL AFFECT THE DOUGH.
IT WILL--
ROASTED MARINATED CHICKEN,
JACK AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA PULL THIS
OVER LIKE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA PINCH THE CORNERS,
PUT IT RIGHT IN THERE.
PUT THIS WEIGHT
RIGHT ON TOP.
AND BYE-BYE,
YOU GO FRY.
HOW LONG?
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE IT
ABOUT A MINUTE AND A HALF,
THEN I'M GONNA TAKE
THE WEIGHT OFF,
AND I'M GONNA FLIP IT.
OH, MY GOSH.
THIS IS WHERE KING KONG
MEETS THE POPOVER... (whistles)
SO WE'RE GONNA HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE CILANTRO CREAM SAUCE.
IT'S GOT HEAVY CREAM, BUTTER,
MILK, CILANTRO, GARLIC SALT
AND FRESH GARLIC.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
THE BEANS, THE RICE,
A LITTLE COTIJA CHEESE,
A LITTLE JACK AND CHEDDAR.
I'M GONNA POP THAT
IN THE OVEN...
FOR ANOTHER THREE MINUTES.
CORRECT--3 MINUTES AT 450
DEGREES IN THE CONVECTION OVEN.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TOP IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF CILANTRO,
CHOPPED ONION,
AVOCADO CREAM.
MMM.
OH, WOW.
EVERYTHING IS DYNAMITE INSIDE.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S NEAT
ABOUT THAT CHICKEN?
IS IT'S BEEN COOKED AND THEN
COOKED AGAIN IN THE FRYER,
AND IT'S NOT DRIED OUT.
NICE AND TENDER.
THE CILANTRO CREAM SAUCE
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT IS DELICIOUS. IT'S STUFFED
WITH A LOT OF MEAT.
CHICKEN, BEEF
OR A PORK CLASSIC...
CARNITAS--IT'S EXCELLENT.
THE MEAT'S TENDER,
AND THE REFRIED BEANS,
VERY GOOD FLAVOR TO 'EM.
YOU KNOW THAT THEY'RE HOMEMADE.
BEST MEXICAN FOOD YOU CAN GET
ANYWHERE AROUND HERE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
MAKES GREAT MEXICAN FOOD?
GREAT MEXICAN FOOD
HAS TO BE KEPT SIMPLE, FRESH,
AND YOU GOTTA GET THE ABSOLUTE
BEST PRODUCT YOU CAN GET.
FOR EVERYTHING,
LIKE FRESH-MADE SALSA,
FIVE KINDS EVERY DAY...
IT TASTES LIKE HE PICKED IT
OUT OF HIS GARDEN YESTERDAY.
FROM THE PICO DE GALLO
TO THE TOMATILLO
TO THIS SWEET HEAT...
PINEAPPLE HABANERO SALSA.
WITH ROASTED JALAPEÑOS,
ONIONS, TOMATOES AND HABANEROS.
THOSE ARE HOT.
TOSS 'EM ON IN.
NOW SOME WATER AND SOME SALT
AND SOME POWER TOOLS.
YAH.
HERE WE GO.
IS THIS THE OFFICIAL
TASTING TECHNIQUE?
YES.
WOW, THAT'S HOT!
THAT'S PRETTY AWESOME.
YEAH, IT IS.
YOU GET A NICE LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR AT THE BEGINNING
FROM THAT PINEAPPLE
AND THEN SMACK.
BAM.
WANT TO BUY AN ICE CUBE
FOR 20 BUCKS?
I CAN PUT THAT ON EVERYTHING,
JUST EAT A COUPLE BOWLS
OF JUST THAT.
BUT AS LONG AS YOU'RE HERE...
THEY HAVE A REALLY
BIG SELECTION.
FAJITAS, QUESADILLAS,
AND WHAT A LOT OF FOLKS CALL
THE STEAK DISH OF ARIZONA...
THIS IS THE NAVAJO TACO.
MADE FROM THE SAME DOUGH
AS THE SOPAPILLA
AND TOPPED WITH BEEF,
CHICKEN OR PORK.
THE FRIED DISK,
FRIED TORTILLA OF SORTS.
SO WHAT'S GONNA BE IN IT?
SLOW-ROASTED PORK.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH A LITTLE GARLIC, SALT,
A LITTLE CRACKED PEPPER,
THE SPANISH PAPRIKA,
MILD RED CHILI,
A LITTLE SUGAR.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA MIX
THAT ALL UP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DUST OUR
ROASTED SLOW PORK WITH THIS.
SO JUST A DRY RUB.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD ABOUT
2 OUNCES OF LIQUID SMOKE
TO THE ROASTING PAN...
AND INTO THE OVEN.
LOW AND SLOW.
THIS IS THE CARNITAS THAT WE
SLOW-ROASTED FOR FIVE HOURS.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON THE FLAT TOP--
EVEN THOUGH
IT'S COOKED AND HOT.
YEP, WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH FRESH ORANGE,
A LITTLE BIT OF PAPRIKA.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TOP
OUR NAVAJO TACO WITH THAT.
GOT IT.
SO WE'VE GOT THIS
BEAUTIFUL FRY BREAD HERE.
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF PINTO BEANS.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS
SLOW-ROASTED CARNITAS.
WE'RE JUST GONNA LAYER A LITTLE
JACK AND CHEDDAR CHEESE,
AND IT GOES BACK IN THE OVEN,
450 DEGREES ABOUT 2 MINUTES.
A LITTLE BIT OF LETTUCE,
SALSA FRESCA,
THE CILANTRO AND ONIONS,
COTIJA CHEESE,
A LITTLE DOLLOP OF SOUR CREAM
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE,
A LITTLE AVOCADO CREAM.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THIS ISN'T
HOW YOU DO IT?
IT IS TODAY.
DON'T YOU MOCK-O MY TACO.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD, MAN.
I GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT ACID
FROM THE ORANGE JUICE.
DELICIOUS. THE PORK
WITH THE PAPRIKA. MMM.
THAT IS A FIRST, MAN.
THAT'S NOT HOW
EVERYBODY EATS IT?
I'VE NEVER
SEEN THAT BEFORE.
I THOUGHT TACO MEANT
PICK IT UP AND EAT IT.
THAT'S AWESOME.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I'VE HAD IT MANY TIMES.
DO YOU ALWAYS USE
A FORK AND KNIFE?
DID YOU HEAR THE NEW RULE JUST
BEEN PASSED BY CITY COUNCIL?
UH-OH.
TODAY WE ARE TAKING AWAY
YOUR FORK AND KNIFE.
IT'S CALLED THE PHILLY HUNCH.
YOU GET UNDERNEATH IT.
N-NO, LIKE THIS.
SEE, EVERYBODY'S DOING IT
THAT WAY, NOT JUST ME.
THIS IS THE BEST IN TOWN.
CARNITAS TACOS.
WHAT MAKES THIS FOOD
SO GREAT?
FRESH INGREDIENTS--
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THE HOMEMADE SALSAS.
CONSISTENTLY GOOD.
I'VE EATEN HERE
TWICE A DAY AT TIMES.
WELL, I'VE BEEN COOKING
ALL MY LIFE.
SALMON TACOS, POR FAVOR.
I'M JUST SO HAPPY
JUST BEING ABLE
TO CHEF IN MY OWN RESTAURANT
AND MAKE GREAT MEXICAN FOOD.
READY?
ALL RIGHT.
AAH!
(man) YEAH.
NEXT STOP ON ROUTE 66--
ALBUQUERQUE...
THE VARIETY
IS WHAT MAKES THIS PLACE.
FOR BOURBON BUTTER
ON A BURGER...
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND DEEP-FRIED TUNA.
COUNTRY-FRIED AHI TUNA.
I WANT TO SEE THIS PULLED OFF.
ROUTE 66 DINERS--
NOW THEY COME IN EVERY SHAPE,
SIZE, COLOR AND STYLE
KIND OF LIKE THIS ONE HERE
IN ALBUQUERQUE, NEW MEXICO.
NOW THE STANDARD DINER STARTED
AS THE CAROTHERS AND MOULDIN
TEXACO STATION BACK IN 1938
AND THEN TURNED INTO A DINER
BACK IN 2006.
NOW FROM WHAT I HEAR,
THERE AIN'T NOTHING STANDARD
ABOUT THE STANDARD DINER.
ORDER IN.
I GOT HOT FOOD
READY TO GO.
IT'S CLASSIC DINER FOOD,
BUT IT'S UPSCALE.
MEAT LOAF WRAPPED IN BACON--
MELTED IN MY MOUTH.
YOU CAN GET HAMBURGER,
OR YOU CAN HAVE AHI TUNA.
THE VARIETY
IS WHAT MAKES THIS PLACE.
YOU GET SOMETHING DIFFERENT
EVERY TIME YOU COME HERE.
YOU KNOW THAT SAYING,
"GET YOUR KICKS ON ROUTE 66"?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT I'M DOING
WITH THE BACON BURGER.
GOOD TO GO.
THANKS TO OWNER
MATT DiGREGORY...
BULLDOG BURGER FOR YOU.
WHO FIRST WALKED INTO THE PLACE
FOR A WHOLE NOTHER REASON.
IN 1990 THIS WAS
A CLASSIC CAR DEALERSHIP.
AND I BOUGHT A 1969 CADILLAC
CONVERTIBLE OUT OF HERE.
PATTY MELT.
I REMEMBER SAYING,
"YOU KNOW,
"THIS WOULD MAKE
A REALLY GREAT RESTAURANT."
16 YEARS LATER, WHEN THIS PART
OF TOWN WAS BEING REBORN,
HE GOT HIS CHANCE.
I KIND OF THOUGHT, LET'S TAKE
A REALLY NICE RESTAURANT,
CALL IT A DINER...
ARE YOU DOING
ALL RIGHT?
IT'S GREAT.
BUT NOT DO
TRADITIONAL DINER FOOD.
EVERYTHING'S GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF A KICKER.
ORDER IN.
SO MATT BROUGHT IN HEAD CHEF
DARIN McHALE
TO CRANK OUT THE KICKERS...
MAC AND CHEESE
COMING UP.
WITH SALMON AND GREEN CHILI...
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING LIKE IT.
IT'S AWESOME.
LAMB LOIN WITH A HOMEMADE
BALSAMIC DEMI-GLACE...
AND THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
FRESH BLACK ANGUS.
EVEN TOPPING A BURGER
WITH BOURBON-INFUSED BUTTER.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
MODERN TECHNIQUES
ON OLD CLASSIC STANDARDS.
LIKE THIS DINER STANDARD.
IT'S NOT YOUR TYPICAL,
YOU KNOW, MOM'S MEAT LOAF.
THE WHOLE THING
IS WRAPPED IN BACON.
ALL RIGHT, CHEF,
WHAT DO WE GOT?
20 POUNDS OF CHUCK.
(whistles)... POOR CHUCK.
SO EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
WE GOT THE EGGS. GO, ROCKY.
SUGAR.
GOLDEN RAISINS.
RAH-SONES.
WE GOT A LITTLE ROSEMARY,
A LITTLE SAGE,
THYME AND PARSLEY, KETCHUP--
IS THAT A FINE
PREPARED KETCHUP?
FANCY.
YELLOW MUSTARD...
A LITTLE BIT OF SOY--
SOY-TENLY...
WORCESTERSHIRE...
ONIONS.
ONIONS IT IS.
OKAY, UH, NO BREADCRUMBS?
WE'RE GONNA ADD BREADCRUMBS WHEN
WE PUT IT IN THE MIXING BOWL.
OH, WE'RE GONNA GO OVER
TO THE BIG HOBART?
YEAH.
YEAH, THAT LOOKS LIKE
A MEAT LOAF PARTY TO ME.
HOLY MOLY. NOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA SHINGLE BACON
ALL THE WAY ACROSS
THIS PIECE OF PAPER.
PUT A LITTLE
OVERLAP ON IT?
YEP.
THERE WE GO.
YOU WANT TO LINE IT ALL UP
SO IT LOOKS GOOD.
MORE BACON.
YOU'RE NOT FAKIN'.
THAT'S A LOT OF BACON.
WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE MEAT LOG
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE BACON,
ROLL THIS THING UP.
SO NOW WHAT DO WE DO WITH IT?
WRAP IT IN FOIL?
WRAP IT IN FOIL.
NOW WHAT TEMPERATURE ARE WE
GONNA PUT IT IN THE OVEN?
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT
IN THE SLOW OVEN
AT 400 DEGREES
FOR A HALF-HOUR.
THEN WE PULL IT OUT.
THEN WE TAKE THE FOIL OFF.
VERY CAREFULLY
CUTTING INTO THE INCISION
OF THE ROLLED LOG
OF PIG AND BEEF.
PUT IT BACK IN THE OVEN
TO CRISP UP THE BACON.
CRISP UP THE BACON
PART OF IT.
AND THEN IT'S READY TO GO.
INSANELY BEAUTIFUL.
(whistles)
THAT'S CRISP MALICIOUS, DUDE.
A FINER LOAF.
I DON'T WANT
THOSE MASHED POTATOES
INTERRUPTING THIS FIRST BITE.
OH.
UH-HUH.
MY GOODNESS, MAN,
I'M TELLING YOU SOMETHING.
IT'S GOT GREAT TEXTURE,
AND IT'S GOT A DEPTH OF FLAVOR.
I GUESS YOU WRAP ANYTHING
IN BACON,
AND THAT IS GONNA MAKE
THE WORLD GO ROUND.
THAT WAS DELICIOUS.
AND I WAS SHOCKED
WHEN I SAW THE RAISINS.
I DIDN'T EXPECT THAT.
IT SCARED YA?
YEAH, FRIGHTENED ME
HALF TO DEATH.
BUT YOU'RE DOING OKAY NOW?
YES, I'M OKAY.
YOU WORKED THROUGH IT?
IT ALWAYS TASTES GOOD. IT'S
GOT A GOOD LITTLE SPIN TO IT.
NOW LET ME GET THE NAME
"STANDARD" STRAIGHT.
"STANDARD" BASICALLY MEANS
A BENCHMARK
THAT ALL OTHERS
ARE COMPARED TO.
IT'S UNIQUE. IT'S INTERESTING,
AND IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
MMM.
YOU KNOW,
YOUR STANDARD BEET BOX
STUFFED WITH FONTINA CHEESE...
THE BEETS ARE ROASTED.
THAT IMPARTS
A NICE LITTLE FLAVOR.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS
TO IT.
FRIED GAME HEN
ON SWEET POTATO PIE...
IT'S VERY SOPHISTICATED.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BUT CHECK OUT WHAT HE'S DOING
WITH SUSHI-GRADE TUNA.
I ORDER IT
EVERY TIME I COME HERE.
COUNTRY-FRIED AHI TUNA.
I WANT TO SEE THIS
PULLED OFF.
A COUPLE PIECES
OF SUSHI-GRADE AHI...
YES.
AND THEN WHAT IS OUR TEMPURA
BATTER MADE OUT OF HERE?
RICE FLOUR, ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
EGGS, SODA WATER.
THEN WE'RE ADDING A LITTLE
SESAME OIL AND SESAME SEEDS.
AND THE KEY
TO A GOOD TEMPURA BATTER
IS KEEPING IT
SUPER, SUPER-COLD.
SUPER-COLD.
SO WE JUST TOOK IT
OUT OF THE ICE OVER THERE.
YES, WE JUST TOOK IT
OUT OF IT.
OKAY, SO GIVE ME A RUNDOWN,
BROTHER.
3 OUNCES
OF THE TEMPURA...
NO FLOUR DREDGE
AHEAD OF TIME?
NO WAY.
REALLY?
NO WAY. I DON'T WANT IT
TO BE A DOUGHNUT.
SO WE HAVE 6 OUNCES
OF AHI HERE.
SO IT'S ALL BATTERED.
NOW WE DROP IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
COOL.
LET'S DO IT.
GO, JOE.
START STRUTTIN'.
DO THE CUTTIN'. WHOA.
THAT RARE WILL SCARE.
WOW.
CONTRAIRE.
MON FRAIRE.
WHAT GOES WITH IT?
WE GOT THE SOY-FRIED
FINGERLING POTATOES--
PARBOILED POTATOES
THAT WE REFRIED.
I LIKE THIS.
AND THEN HERE'S MY
FAVORITE--WASABI GUACAMOLE--
AVOCADOS, GARLIC,
TOMATO, CILANTRO,
WASABI POWDER, LIME JUICE
AND THEN TARTAR,
CILANTRO AND A TON
OF PICKLED GINGER IN THERE.
MMM.
THAT IS GREAT.
THAT'S ON-POINT, DUDE.
IT WAS A REAL NICE,
LIGHT HIT OF THE TEMPURA.
GOTTA KEEP THE TUNA SUPER-COLD
AND THE BATTER SUPER-COLD,
FRYER AT THE RIGHT TEMP,
SMACK IT.
NICE.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
THE TEXTURE OF THE TUNA
IS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
AS TENDER AS CAN BE.
IT HAS A GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
(man)
BOURBON BUTTER BURGER UP.
THIS IS REALLY
A ONE-OF-A-KIND PLACE.
EVERYTHING THAT YOU GET
IS JUST GREAT.
AND A STANDARD FINER LOAF
FOR YOU.
EVERY VISIT TO THE STANDARD
DINER IS A GOOD ONE.
THE BACON IS JUST GREAT.
I THINK YOU COULD
WRAP MY SHOE IN BACON...
IT WOULD PROBABLY
TASTE GOOD, RIGHT?
IT'D BE ALL RIGHT.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
GRAVY ON THERE, YOU KNOW?
UP NEXT...
CHICKEN BASKET UP.
OUTSIDE CHICAGO...
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
TO A ROUTE 66 LEGEND...
IT'S THE CHICKEN.
WHERE FOLKS HAVE BEEN
LOVIN' THE SAME THING...
IT'S BEEN AROUND
FOR YEARS AND YEARS.
FOR MORE THAN 60 YEARS.
(whistles)...
THAT'S SOME CHICKEN HISTORY.
YES, IT IS.
IT WAS BACK IN THE '40s THIS
PLACE STARTED FRYIN' UP CHICKEN
FOR DRIVERS ON THE OLD ROUTE 66
HERE IN WILLOWBROOK, ILLINOIS.
WELL, THEN THE NEW HIGHWAY
WAS BUILT,
AND A LOT OF FOLKS TOOK IT.
THAT DIDN'T CLOSE THIS PLACE.
DELL RHEA'S CHICKEN BASKET
IS IN THE ILLINOIS ROUTE 66
HALL OF FAME
AND FOR GOOD REASON.
IT'S THE CHICKEN.
TWO CHICKEN DINNERS.
THEY'RE FAMOUS FOR THEIR
CHICKEN, AND I LOVE IT.
THIS IS MY SECOND HELPING.
CHICKEN BASKET UP.
THIS IS SO GOOD.
IT'S BEEN AROUND
FOR YEARS AND YEARS.
THIS FRIED CHICKEN RECIPE
HAS BEEN GOING ON HERE
SINCE THE '30s?
MID TO LATE '30s.
WE'RE NOT SURE
OF THE EXACT DATE.
(whistles)
THAT'S SOME CHICKEN HISTORY.
YES, IT IS.
HANDED DOWN
TO OWNER PATRICK RHEA...
SIX UP, PLEASE.
FROM HIS DAD DELL
WHO BOUGHT THE PLACE IN '63.
I WAS 9 YEARS OLD.
SO YOU WERE IN HERE
AT 9 YEARS OLD...
BUSING TABLES,
WASHING GLASSES...
AND LEARNING HOW TO KEEP FOLKS
COMING BACK.
THAT'S TWO CHICKEN BASKETS UP.
IT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
I DO EVERYTHING LIKE I DO--
I DO IT FROM SCRATCH.
I DO IT HOMEMADE.
AND HE'S DOING IT BY THE TON...
GET THOSE TWO CHICKENS ON.
SERIOUSLY, 2,000 POUNDS A WEEK.
WALK ME THROUGH
THE PRINCIPLES.
WE'RE GONNA BRINE THIS.
TAKE SOME SALT.
IT GIVES THE MEAT
THE FLAVOR.
AND SOME SUGAR?
NO SUGAR.
THAT'S INTERESTING.
NOW HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA STAY IN SALT?
THIS IS GONNA STAY IN SALT
FOR 24 HOURS
BEFORE WE DO
ANYTHING TO IT.
MAKES A PROFOUND DIFFERENCE,
YOU SAY.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA WHAT?
BREAD IT WITH FLOUR, MILK
AND A SPECIAL BREADCRUMB WE USE.
IT COMES ONLY FROM A CHICAGO
BAKERY--EXTRA-FINE GRAIN.
NOW DO YOU LET THIS SET UP ON
THIS BREADING HERE FOR A WHILE?
YEAH, THIS HAS GOTTA SIT FOR
BETWEEN FOUR AND SIX HOURS.
ONCE THOSE JUICES KIND OF WORK
INTO THOSE BREADCRUMBS
AND IT KIND OF ALL STICKS
TOGETHER, THEN WE'LL FRY IT,
WHAT, ABOUT 350, 325?
NO, THAT'S PART
OF OUR SECRET.
WE COOK AT A VERY
DIFFERENT TEMPERATURE.
WE'RE AT 260.
COOK FOR 20 MINUTES.
NO.
YEP.
NOW THIS IS NOT
WHAT YOU WOULD CALL
A SOUTHERN
HARD-FRIED CHICKEN.
INTERESTING.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS.
44 YEARS
I'VE BEEN HERE.
EVERY TIME I EAT THIS CHICKEN
IT AMAZES ME.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
SO YOU LET IT SIT
AND DRAIN A LITTLE BIT?
LET IT SIT AND DRAIN.
LET IT COOL DOWN.
LET THE JUICES
COAGULATE A LITTLE BIT.
GOTTA LET YOUR JUICES
COAGULATE.
YOU'VE GOT TO DO THAT.
THERE SHE IS.
LOOK HOW TENDER THAT IS--
JUST JUICY,
FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
HMM, REALLY NICE
CRUNCHY COATING.
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT,
YOU'RE GETTING GOOD BREADING
AND GOOD BIRD.
YOU REALLY PICK UP THAT SALT.
IT'S GOT SOME NICE FLAVOR TO IT.
BREADING, AS SIMPLE AS IT IS,
IT COATS WELL WITH THE CHICKEN.
IT MAKES IT NICE AND--
NICE AND CRUNCHY.
YOU CAN TELL I DIDN'T LIKE IT.
GOOD CHICKEN.
THANK YOU.
THE CHICKEN IS SO MOIST.
I LOVE THE BREADING.
THE BREADING IS KEY.
IT'S VERY LIGHT AND FRESH.
GREAT FLAVOR.
SUPER-TINY FLAKY
FALL-APARTY.
THE WAY IT'S BEEN FOR DECADES.
EVERY TIME WE COME HERE,
EXACTLY THE SAME.
A THROWBACK FROM LIKE
THE '50s OR '60s,
SOMETHING MY PARENTS
WOULD HAVE COME TO.
NOW I CAN EXPERIENCE THE SAME
THING THAT THEY EXPERIENCED.
THANK YOU.
FROM THEIR ORIGINAL
FRIED CHICKEN
TO EVERYTHING THAT'S BEEN ADDED
OVER THE YEARS,
LIKE ROASTED CHICKEN
AND CHICKEN POTPIE...
AND THE SOUP.
THAT'S BE CHICKEN DUMPLIN',
AND GET THIS...
MY HUSBAND LIKES THE GIZZARDS,
BUT I'VE NEVER TASTED ONE.
PATRICK'S EVEN DOING
HIS OWN TAKE
ON THIS BAR FOOD CLASSIC...
12-PIECE BUFFALO WING UP.
I'VE HEARD ALREADY
THROUGH THE GRAPEVINE
THAT YOU'RE PLANNING ON BREADING
THIS BUFFALO WINGS.
I DIP 'EM
IN SOME FLOUR.
THAT IS NOT OKAY.
IT'S GOTTA HAVE--
I'M JUST TELLIN' YA,
I'M GONNA BE HARD-PRESSED
TO LIKE THESE.
I MIGHT EVEN POUT
DURING THIS.
SEE WHAT HAPPENS
AT THE END.
1/2 CUP OF SALT,
1/4 CUP OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLACK PEPPER,
WHITE PEPPER, CAYENNE.
(whistles)
A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT THERE.
A LITTLE BIT.
SO HOW LONG
DO THEY MARINATE?
24 HOURS.
AND THEN YOU
DREDGE 'EM AROUND?
YEP.
THEN THEY GET FRIED.
WHILE THESE ARE FRYIN', WE'LL
MAKE SOME BLUE CHEESE DRESSING.
YES, SIR.
START OUT WITH SOME MAYONNAISE.
ADD BUTTERMILK.
I USUALLY HAVE ABOUT
2 OR 3 QUARTS OF THIS
IN THE MORNING
BEFORE I JOG.
NEXT ITEM
IS SOUR CREAM.
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
WORCESTERSHIRE, WHITE PEPPER...
OKAY.
I'VE GOT
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC.
THAT'S THE WAY YOU ROLL.
AND STIR THIS UP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF BLUE CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE DARK VEINS.
THAT IS SOME
DYNAMITE BLUE CHEESE.
OUR WINGS ALMOST DONE?
YEAH, I THINK
OUR WINGS ARE DONE.
I LIKE 'EM
EXTRA CRISPY.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAUCE.
HOT PEPPERED CAYENNE SAUCE.
EXACTLY.
ADD MELTED BUTTER TO IT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE SCARED.
OH, NO, IT'S FINE.
THAT'S A BIG PORTION
OF WINGS.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
I MEAN, IT REALLY IS.
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE AND JUICY.
MMM.
BLUE CHEESE IS NICE
AND CREAMY, TANGY.
YOU KNOW WHAT I REALLY LIKE
ABOUT THAT?
IS IT HOLDS ON
TO SOME OF THE HERBS
AND SOME OF THE SPICES.
LOOK AT HOW JUICY IT IS,
GOOD HEAT, NOT TOO SPICY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT WAS A GOOD WING.
WE'RE NOT GONNA HAVE TO FIGHT
OVER THIS NOW, ARE WE?
WE'RE NOT GONNA GO
TO THE GROUND ON THIS.
OKAY.
PEACE, UNITY, TREATY WING.
YOU GOT A THING ABOUT YOUR WING.
THE HOT WINGS WERE ESPECIALLY
GREAT. REALLY NICE AND SPICY.
VERY GOOD WINGS.
THE CHICKEN IS EXCELLENT,
FRESH ALL THE TIME.
LIKE ALMOST EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU.
THE MASHED POTATOES AND GRAVY
ARE MY FAVORITE.
ONE BAKED
MACARONI AND CHEESE.
MY SON RYDER
WOULD FLIP OUT FOR THIS.
EACH DISH BAKED TO ORDER
WHEN WE COME BACK.
FINALLY COOLING DOWN
TO THE POINT
WHERE I CAN START
TO SHOVEL IT IN.
TWO CHICKEN BASKETS...
AT DELL RHEA'S CHICKEN BASKET
ON ROUTE 66 OUTSIDE CHICAGO...
THE CHICKEN IS HOT.
THEY'VE BEEN DOING CHICKEN
THE SAME WAY SINCE '46.
REALLY GOOD,
REALLY, REALLY TASTY.
THE BREADING ON THE OUTSIDE--
I LIKE THAT A LOT.
AND OWNER PATRICK RHEA...
IS EVERYTHING OKAY?
IS STILL USING THE SAME RECIPE
HE GOT FROM HIS DAD.
HE'S BEEN AROUND A LONG TIME.
A TRADITION
OF HOME-MAKIN' CHICKEN...
HERE YOU ARE.
AND THE SIDES
THAT COME WITH IT.
TWO CORNCOBS, PLEASE.
THE MASHED POTATOES AND GRAVY
ARE MY FAVORITE.
THE GRAVY IS EXCELLENT.
BUT I ALSO LIKE
THE CORN FRITTERS.
EVERYTHING HAS BEEN EXCELLENT.
AND THEY'RE DOING THIS
COMFORT FOOD CLASSIC...
YOU HAVE A MAC AND CHEESE.
ONE ORDER AT AT TIME.
MACARONI AND CHEESE--
ALL BASIC OLD-SCHOOL--
BUTTER AND FLOUR, MAKE A LITTLE
OLD-FASHIONED ROUX.
OKAY.
EQUAL PARTS.
EQUAL PARTS--ONE TO ONE--
SAUTE SOME ONIONS.
GUY, WOULD YOU HAND ME
THAT WINE OVER THERE?
I WAS JUST
DRINKING THAT.
NOW YOU MADE
THIS RECIPE UP?
YES, I DID.
I TOOK SOME OLD CLASSICS,
TUNED 'EM UP JUST A LITTLE BIT.
WHILE THAT'S COOKING,
I'M GONNA START
ADDING SOME SEASONINGS
TO THIS...
ALL RIGHT.
SALT, WHITE PEPPER, THYME.
THYME.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A SAVORY SAUCE
OUT OF IT ANYWAY,
SO I THINK THE THYME
GOES WELL WITH THE CHEESE.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR ONION,
WINE AND BUTTER...
OKAY.
ADD THE ROUX,
COOK IT ALL TOGETHER.
SO WE'VE GOT OUR BéCHAMEL
JUST ABOUT TO THE CONSISTENCY
WE WANT IT--NICE AND TIGHT.
IT TIGHTENS UP NICE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A BUNCH OF SEASONINGS--
DRY MUSTARD,
SALT, WHITE PEPPER...
PAPRIKA FOR
A LITTLE COLOR.
PAPRIKA.
NOW WHAT KIND OF CHEESE
ARE WE GONNA ADD?
WE USE THREE KINDS.
I'M GONNA USE PARMESAN.
I'M GONNA USE ASIAGO.
AND I'M GONNA USE
SHARP CHEDDAR.
DO YOU ADD IT IN
ALL AT ONE TIME,
OR DO YOU GO
LITTLE BY LITTLE?
I PRETTY MUCH ADD 'EM
ONE AT A TIME.
GET THIS
MELTED IN THERE,
AND WE'LL ADD
THE OTHER TWO CHEESES.
IF YOU WANT TO DUMP THAT ASIAGO
IN, THAT'D BE GREAT. PARMESAN.
I LIKE THAT, SO YOU GET A LITTLE
BIT OF THE SWEET AND SHARP
FROM THE ASIAGO
AND THE PARM
AND THE CREAMINESS
FROM THE CHEDDAR.
OKAY, CHEESE SAUCE IS DONE.
WE'LL TAKE THAT WITH THE PASTA,
PUT IT IN THE DISH
AND BAKE IT.
SHOULDN'T WE TASTE THAT?
THAT'S CREAMY GOODNESS.
IT'S LIKE
THE COLORADO CHEESE RIVER
RUNNING RIGHT THROUGH
FLAVOR TOWN.
MACARONI.
SO EVERY TIME
SOMEBODY ORDERS THIS,
YOU COOK THE PASTA
TO ORDER?
YES, SIR.
THAT'S WHAT YOU DO
IN ITALIAN RESTAURANTS.
YOU COOK YOUR PASTA FIRST.
NO, I'M DOWN WITH IT.
COOL.
I'M PICKIN' UP WHAT YOU'RE
LAYIN' DOWN, BROTHER.
YEAH, AND THEN SOME MORE
ON WOULD BE GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT MORE CHEESE.
IN THE OVEN SHE GOES.
ABOUT TEN MINUTES
OF KNICK KNACK PADDY WHACK?
IT'S ABOUT 20, ACTUALLY.
I LIKE TO GET IT--YEAH.
REALLY?
OH, SO YOU REALLY LIKE
TO LET IT CARAMELIZE.
I LIKE NICE AND BROWN
ON THE TOP.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE'S NOT MANY PLACES
YOU FIND ANYMORE
WHERE YOU GET CUSTOM-MADE
MAC AND CHEESE.
MMM, THAT'S CREAMY.
GOOD.
THAT'S MAC AND CHEESE
RIGHT THERE.
THAT SHARP CHEDDAR--
REALLY NICE, VELVETY, MMM.
DOING THIS RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE CAPTAIN CREAMY NOW.
MY SON HUNTER OR RYDER
WOULD GO BANANAS FOR THIS.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT BANANAS ARE?
KIND OF LIKE ORANGES?
BANANAS ARE GOOD.
SILLY CAPTAIN CREAMY.
THE MAC AND CHEESE
WAS EXCELLENT, JUST RIGHT.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
GOOD EATING EXPERIENCE
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
THIS IS SATISFYING MY HUNGER.
THAT'S WHAT
I LIKE TO HEAR.
I KNOW. I SAID I DIDN'T LIKE
BREADED WINGS.
I JUST DIDN'T FEEL GOOD,
I GUESS, TO SIT HERE
AND NOT EAT ALL OF THEM...
AND THE FRIED CHICKEN
AND THE MAC AND CHEESE.
YOU WOULD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YA
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
I GOT AN ACE OF LOAF.
HEY, I WANT YOU TO HEAR WHAT
USED TO BE MY RINGTONE.
(Guy) on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."
NO.
YEAH.