HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU HAVE THE TAMALE THERE.
NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITES.
FEELS LIKE HOME.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS EVERY TIME.
IN SANTA FE...
THIS IS CRAZY TASTY.
SALVADORAN HOME COOKING...
THERE'S A BURST OF FLAVORS.
AND SOUTHWESTERN
COMFORT FOOD...
NICE AND SPICY,
IT'S LIKE, WHOO.
FROM A LOCAL COUPLE...
WE LIVE
DOWN THE STREET.
ADAM.
HEY.
WHEN THE CHEESE
IS OOZING OUT LIKE LAVA
OVER IN FLAVOR-TOWN VOLCANO,
YOU GOT ISSUES.
YOU GOT TO COME CHECK IT OUT.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU. BANANAS.
IN SALT LAKE CITY...
USUALLY YOU GOT TO GO
TO OKLAHOMA FOR THIS.
BARBECUED EVERYTHING...
I LOVE THEIR BRISKET.
PULLED PORK,
LOVE IT.
I'VE GOT THE RIBS,
REALLY GOOD.
AND A HOUSE SPECIAL...
BURNT ENDS.
THAT'S REALLY WORTH THE WAIT...
DUDE. MMM.
MMM.
IT DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER
THAN THAT.
AND IN MISSISSIPPI...
VERY GOOD, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT HITS YOUR TASTE BUDS.
A JOINT ON THE BAYOU...
MISSISSIPPI COASTAL CUISINE.
A LOT OF FRESH SEAFOOD.
CRAB CLAWS.
HERE WE GO.
WHOA.
SERVING THE SAME FAVORITES...
A SEAFOOD GUMBO.
FOR 47 YEARS.
YOU GOT TASTE-A-VISION ON
AT HOME?
TRY THIS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M ROLLING THROUGH
SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO,
AND I'M TAKING YOU
TO A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S PROBABLY LIKE
A PERFECT EXAMPLE
OF WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR HERE
ON TRIPLE "D."
IT'S OWNED BY
A HUSBAND AND WIFE TEAM.
THEY'RE SCRATCH-COOKING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
THE PLACE IS JUST FULL
OF CHARACTER,
AND THE NEIGHBORHOOD
TOTALLY DIGS IT.
YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT
TUNE-UP CAFé.
YOU HAVE THE TAMALE THERE.
THIS IS
A VERY LOCAL SPOT.
IT'S IN MY NEIGHBORHOOD.
WHAT DO WE GOT?
RUN BY A COUPLE
FROM THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
WE LIVE
DOWN THE STREET.
ADAM.
HEY.
FEELS LIKE HOME.
YEAH.
EL SALVADOR NATIVE
JESúS RIVERA...
CORN TORTILLA.
AND HIS WIFE CHARLOTTE
BOUGHT THIS PLACE
LESS THAN A YEAR AGO.
JESúS WAS WORKING AT TWO
RESTAURANTS AT THE SAME TIME,
AND I THOUGHT,
IF HE'S WORKING THAT HARD,
HE SHOULD HAVE
HIS OWN PLACE.
HEY.
SO NOW HE'S CRANKING OUT
COMFORT FOOD...
STUFFED FRENCH TOAST HAS
A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM CHEESE.
SOUTHWESTERN FAVORITES...
THE CHILE RELLENOS--CHILE PEPPER
STUFFED WITH CHEESE.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
PUPUSAS.
AND THIS EL SALVADORAN DISH
JESúS GREW UP WITH.
CORNMEAL STUFFED
WITH FLANK STEAK,
CORN AND GREEN CHILIES.
STARTS OUT VERY MILD, AND THEN
THERE'S A BURST OF FLAVOR.
OH.
THIS IS GONNA BE THE BEEF
THAT'S GONNA GO IN THE PUPUSA.
YEAH.
OKAY. SO NOW
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL DOWN.
YEAH.
SO YOU SAUTé THE ONIONS
DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
AND NEXT, GARLIC.
OKAY, SO THOSE ARE SAUTéED
FOR TEN MINUTES. THEN WHAT?
THIS IS THE FLANK STEAK.
WOW, WE'RE MAKING
A LOT.
YEAH, I LOVE FLANK STEAK, TOO.
SO THAT'LL ALL BROWN UP.
AND NOW IT'S TIME FOR
THE TOMATOES AND THE PEPPERS.
CHILE PASADO.
YEAH.
SALT AND PEPPER.
SO THEN COOK ALL THAT UP.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THIS.
HOW LONG
IS IT GONNA TAKE?
ONE HOUR'S ENOUGH.
I DON'T THINK THAT
I'VE EVER HAD PUPUSA.
I'LL MAKE ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, MASECA, SALT,
OIL, WATER,
SOME MASA.
MASA, WHICH IS LIKE
WE MAKE A TORTILLA WITH.
TORTILLA MASA.
OKAY.
THIS IS FOR YOU.
THAT'S HOW HE DID IT.
NEXT.
JESúS, MY BROTHER,
THEY HAVE THESE THINGS
CALLED A TORTILLA PRESS.
YEAH.
I'M GONNA GET YOU ONE
FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY.
OKAY.
DO LIKE THE METHOD, THOUGH.
WE'RE MAKING A THICKER
THAN AN AVERAGE TORTILLA.
YOU DON'T SKIMP ON THE PORTIONS.
YOU GIVE A LOT.
YEAH. ENOUGH.
NEXT IS CORN,
MONTERREY JACK CHEESE.
MONTERREY JACK CHEESE...
YEAH.
WITH THE EL SALVADORIAN DISH.
YEAH, OKAY.
THIS IS FOR YOU,
STARTING RIGHT HERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF CORN.
YOU'RE DOING GOOD.
OKAY, I'M ALL RIGHT
SO FAR?
YEAH.
I'M GRADUATING HERE
AT THE TUNE-UP CULINARY
EDUCATION CENTER?
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
FOLD THE PUPUSA.
PUT IN THE MIDDLE LIKE THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
NEXT--
SO THAT'S WHY YOU DON'T USE
THE TORTILLA PRESS,
'CAUSE YOU GOT HAVE THEM
ON THE PAPER.
YEAH.
YOU WANT TO JUST KIND OF MAKE IT
INTO A ROUND PATTY.
I WRAPPED THIS IN TINFOIL,
I COULD COOK THIS
ON THE MANIFOLD
OF MY '67 OUT THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE COOK THE PUPUSA.
LET IT BOIL.
WE DON'T WANT
THE HEAT TOO HIGH.
WE DON'T WANT IT TO BROWN
TOO FAST WITHOUT COOKING IT.
YEAH.
SO NOW WE FLIP 'EM OVER?
LIKE THIS.
OH.
PERFECT.
LOOK, THIS IS
THE CHEESE MELTING INSIDE.
UH-HUH, I CAN SEE IT.
THIS IS READY. LET'S GO PUT
TOMATO SAUCE ON TOP.
THE ROASTED TOMATO SALSA,
SALT AND PEPPER, ONIONS,
JALAPEÑOS, THE CILANTRO
AND THE GARLIC.
LOOK AT THAT.
TRY IT.
MMM. CRAZY GOOD.
IF THE MEAT WASN'T GOOD ENOUGH
JUST BY ITSELF,
THE CRISPY, CRUNCHY MASA
ON THE OUTSIDE
WITH THE CORN AND THE CHEESE
OOZING OUT OF IT--MMM.
THAT DOES IT.
YOU HAVE COMPLETELY
TRAIN-WRECKED ME, MAN.
THAT'S AWESOME, MAN,
SERIOUSLY.
OKAY.
NICE AND CRISPY AND CRUNCHY
ON THE OUTSIDE.
REALLY LIGHT.
IT HAS A DIFFERENT FLAVOR
THAN ANYTHING ELSE
THAT I'VE EATEN HERE IN TOWN.
OH, THAT'S ME.
AND THE LOCALS
JUST CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF IT.
I'M HERE A COUPLE TIMES A WEEK.
SOMETIMES I'VE EATEN HERE
TWICE A DAY.
THERE YOU GO.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS EVERY TIME.
IT'S GREAT, YEAH.
AND EVERYBODY'S JUST HAVING
A GREAT TIME BEING HERE.
IT FEELS SO COMFORTABLE.
YOU CAN SIT AT THE COMMUNITY
TABLE AND MEET THE PEOPLE.
GET WHATEVER
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR.
MAKE ME
A BANANA LEAF TAMALE.
MMM. WOW.
THIS IS CRAZY TASTY.
AND THE FISH TACOS.
WATERMELON GAZPACHO,
OH, IS IT GOOD.
A RELLENO.
EVEN THE CLASSICS GET
A TUNE-UP TWIST.
THE CHILE RELLENO
IS A COMMON DISH IN SANTA FE,
BUT HERE IT'S DIFFERENT.
AMAZING.
THEY'RE SO LIGHTLY BREADED,
AND IT REALLY BRINGS OUT
THE CHILE FLAVOR.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE ANAHEIMS,
AND THIS IS GONNA BE
FOR OUR CHILE RELLENOS?
YEAH, CHILE RELLENOS.
WE'RE NOT GONNA PUT
ANYTHING ON THEM?
NO.
JUST THROW IT ON THE GRILL.
YOU LINE 'EM UP, LET 'EM ROAST,
AND THEN WHEN THEY GET DONE,
YOU'RE GONNA SWEAT 'EM.
THEY'VE COOLED DOWN.
NOW YOU TAKE THE SKIN OFF.
SO NOW I JUST GIVE IT
A LITTLE TEAR INTO THERE.
PULL THE SEEDS OUT,
AS MUCH AS YOU CAN.
WE'RE MAKING
A LITTLE POCKET HERE.
WE HAVE
ONIONS AND CHEESE.
MONTERREY JACK CHEESE.
IT'S ALL MIXED TOGETHER.
YEAH.
MAKE A LITTLE CHEESE TORPEDO.
WELL, FRANKLY, MA'AM, I--
OKAY, SO NOW...
PUT THE CHEESE
INSIDE THE CHILE.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU'VE GOT IT.
SO WE GOT 'EM DONE.
WE PUT IN THE FREEZER...
REALLY?
FOR 20 MINUTES.
SO THEY'RE FIRM.
NOW WE MAKE THE BATTER?
THE BATTER, YEAH.
WE SEPARATE THE EGGS.
OKAY, SO WE GOT
ALL THE WHITES IN.
WHEN THIS IS FLUFFY,
I PUT IN THE EGG YOLKS, FLOUR.
THIS IS GONNA MAKE IT
A REALLY NICE LIGHT BATTER
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THIS.
I MIX BY HAND, YEAH.
BY HAND, OKAY.
SO NOW WE GRAB ALL OF THIS
AND GO OVER HERE AND FRY 'EM?
YEAH.
A LITTLE FLOUR SO
THE BATTER'LL STICK TO THEM.
NOW IT'S READY.
WOW.
(whistles)
THOSE GO FAST, HUH?
YEAH.
LOOK AT THOSE.
BEAUTIFUL, BABY.
SO THEY'RE DONE.
NOW HOW DO WE MAKE A PLATE?
SO A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ROASTED TOMATO SALSA.
CHEESE...
PUT A LITTLE MELT ON IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
REFRITOS,
THE TORTILLA HERE.
AND THAT'S HOW SHE COMES.
WHEN THE CHEESE
IS OOZING OUT LIKE LAVA
OVER IN FLAVOR-TOWN VOLCANO,
YOU'VE GOT ISSUES.
MMM. MMM!
THAT'S MONEY, DUDE.
I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
I'VE NEVER BEEN THAT MUCH
OF A CHILE RELLENO FAN,
TYPICALLY BECAUSE THE BATTER
IS TOO EGGY.
THIS IS LIGHT AND CREAMY
AND TENDER.
I MEAN, JUST CUT IT
WITH A FORK AND--
ON POINT.
I'M A HUGE FAN OF THAT.
THE RELLENOS ARE EXCELLENT.
IT'S NICE AND SPICY,
IT'S LIKE, WHOO.
INSIDE THE CHEESE IS JUST
OOZING, AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOR YOU.
YES, THANK YOU.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO COME
FOR FANTASTIC FOOD.
BURRITO, RED.
IF SOMEONE IS HAPPY
AND LOVES MAKING FOOD,
IT COMES OUT IN THE TASTE.
MMM.
THIS IS
THE AMERICAN DREAM...
RIGHT HERE.
I LOOK AT YOU DOING IT NOW,
BUT, I TELL YOU SOMETHING,
THIS GUY'S A WORKING MACHINE,
ISN'T HE?
THERE'S NONE BETTER.
I THINK YOU MIGHT WANT TO THINK
ABOUT EXPANDING.
TWO WALLS ARE GONNA NEED
TO BE PUSHED OUT.
YOU GOT TO COME CHECK IT OUT.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU. BANANAS.
UP NEXT WE'RE HEADING
TO SALT LAKE CITY...
THIS IS THE GOOD STUFF.
WHERE YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT WHAT
THEY'RE DOING WITH THE BRISKET.
DUDE. THAT IS
WHAT THEY CALL A BURNT END. MMM.
SO GOOD.
IS THAT MONEY?
THAT'S CHA-CHING MONEY.
WHEN YOU'RE THINKING BARBECUE,
YOU'RE PROBABLY THINKING
MEMPHIS, TEXAS, THE CAROLINAS.
I DO NOT BELIEVE YOU'RE THINKING
UTAH IN THE WASATCH MOUNTAINS.
BUT WHEN YOU PUT DOWN
YOUR SNOWBOARD
AND YOU'RE HEADING BACK
FROM PARK CITY
ON YOUR WAY THROUGH
TO SALT LAKE,
WELL, YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT
THIS JOINT
RUN BY A COMPETITION
BARBECUE DUDE NAMED PAT.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
(man) THIS IS WONDERFUL.
WE'RE LUCKY HERE IN SALT LAKE,
'CAUSE WE GOT PAT.
I'M FROM CHICAGO,
AND FINDING A GOOD RIB PLACE
IN SALT LAKE'S A GOOD THING.
USUALLY YOU GOT TO GO
TO OKLAHOMA FOR THIS.
SOME GOOD BARBECUE...
THAT FOR OWNER PAT BARBER
STARTED OUT AS A HOBBY.
YOU DO
A BARBECUE COMPETITION.
YOU GET TO A POINT
WHERE YOU SAY,
"IF I WIN BIG,
I'M DOING THIS."
IF I COME IN TENTH PLACE
IN ANY CATEGORY,
I'M QUITTING MY DAY JOB.
A BUNCH OF BLUE RIBBONS
AND SIX YEARS LATER...
LOOK WHAT'S HAPPENED.
IT'S LIKE THE CIRCUS
CAME TO TOWN.
YEAH.
I NEED A PULLED PORK, 13-H.
WITH PAT AND HIS CREW
CRANKING OUT MORE THAN
2,000 MEALS A WEEK...
IT'S THE BEST IN TOWN.
ALL FROM A SMOKER
PARKED OUTSIDE...
YOU HAVE YOURS STATIONARY
OR ON A TRAILER?
IT'S ON A TRAILER.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS A CULINARY GANGSTER
RIGHT HERE. THIS GUY ROLLS OUT.
SMOKING UP THE SAME RECIPES
THAT GOT HIM THOSE RIBBONS.
I LOVE THEIR BRISKET.
PULLED PORK,
LOVE IT.
I'VE GOT THE RIBS,
REALLY GOOD.
BUT IT'S A ONE-OF-A-KIND,
ONCE-A-WEEK SPECIALTY...
BURNT ENDS.
THAT'S GOT 'EM LINING UP
AND WAITING TILL THEY'RE READY.
YOU'RE LUCKY IF YOU GET 'EM.
THEY GO SO FAST.
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL--
THE REASON THAT WE COME
TO PAT'S.
PEOPLE LINING UP A HALF AN HOUR
TO AN HOUR BEFORE YOU OPEN
TO GET
THE SPECIAL OF THE DAY.
THIS IS A TREAT.
HUNKS OF BRISKET DOUBLED-RUBBED
AND SMOKED TWICE.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT BRISKET.
HOW MUCH ARE YOU GONNA
TRIM DOWN ON THAT?
I'M NOT GONNA TRIM
ANY OF IT.
OH, I LOVE IT. FAT'S FLAVOR,
FAT'S MOISTURE.
YOU BETCHA.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA MAKE UP
A BLEND HERE.
THE RUB THAT YOU USE
IN COMPETITION?
YES.
A PRODUCT CALLED BUTT RUB.
BUTT RUB IS ACTUALLY
A FAMOUS BARBECUE TEAM,
AND THIS IS THE GOODS.
YEAH.
WE ADD A STEAK SEASONING TO IT
AND THEN CHILI POWDER TO IT.
THEN WHAT'S THIS?
THIS IS
MY SIGNATURE INGREDIENT.
IT'S FROM
OUT OF THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS THE MAGIC.
THIS IS
THE "WE'RE NOT GONNA REVEAL IT."
WE'RE NOT GONNA REVEAL IT.
WOW.
LET'S PUT IT ON THERE.
AND THEN...
LET IT SIT OVERNIGHT,
'CAUSE WE WANT ALL THOSE SPICES
TO MARRY INTO THAT MEAT.
THIS IS THE ROUTINE
EVERY TIME?
WE WHEEL IT DOWN
THE BIG HALLWAY?
YES.
LET'S GO AHEAD,
AND WE'LL PUT OUR BRISKET ON.
THEN TEN HOURS LATER...
LET'S SEE
WHAT WE GOT.
THE BRISKET'S DONE.
GORGEOUS.
WE'RE GONNA PULL 'EM,
TAKE THE CAPS OFF,
RUB 'EM AGAIN, AND WE'LL COME
BACK TO THIS FOR OUR BURNT ENDS.
YOU GOT IT.
SHOW ME WHAT WE GOT, BOSS.
OKAY.
YOU KNOW RIGHT WHERE TO GO.
YEAH, THAT'S A CAP.
THAT'S A FLAT.
NOW WHAT WE'LL DO IS TRIM
SOME OF THIS FAT OFF HERE.
PUT MORE RUB ON HERE.
THAT'S WHAT HEAVEN LOOKS LIKE
RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW THAT'S GONNA GO
HOW MUCH LONGER?
THIS WILL COOK
FOR TEN HOURS.
LOOK AT THOSE.
THOSE LOOK AWESOME.
I LIKE THAT ONE.
THIS ONE?
THAT ONE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GOOD CHOICE?
IT'S PERFECT.
AND LOOK AT THAT.
DUDE. MMM.
IS THAT MONEY?
DUDE, THAT'S CHA-CHING MONEY.
JUST ENOUGH MARBLING
IN THERE,
SAVORY AND CRUNCHY ENOUGH,
OH.
TRY THAT ONE.
THAT IS WHAT
THEY CALL A BURNT END.
YOU'RE NOT DOING THIS WRONG
AT ALL. MMM.
REALLY JUICY.
MMM. SO GOOD.
I LOVE THE SMOKY FLAVOR
OF THE MEAT.
DELICIOUS.
THIS IS THE GOOD STUFF.
YOU GOT TO COME EARLY
TO GET THE SPECIAL.
PEOPLE ARE WAITING
IN LINE DOWN THERE.
OH, YEAH.
THE LINE'S RIDICULOUS.
FOR EVERYTHING
PAT'S CRANKING OUT.
I EITHER HAVE TO GET RIBS
OR BRISKET EVERY WEEKEND.
THE PULLED PORK
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
HOWEVER YOU WANT IT.
I GOT 3-MEAT OR A 4-MEAT COMBO,
2-MEAT COMBO.
WHAT DO YOU GOT THERE?
CHICKEN, RIBS AND PORK.
AND JUST A LITTLE SLAW
TO GET IN THE WAY.
VERY GOOD SIDES.
EVERYTHING YOU'D EXPECT
LIKE COLESLAW AND CORNBREAD...
IT'S VERY BUTTERY, TOUCH
OF HONEY IN IT. IT'S THE BEST.
AND SOME THINGS YOU WOULDN'T.
GOOD CALL.
RED BEANS AND RICE,
EXCELLENT, EXCELLENT.
OR HOW ABOUT FRESH-SMOKED
CHICKEN AND SAUSAGE...
IT'S JUST LIKE
THE BIG FOOD-GIVER HERE.
YEAH, IT IS.
FOR NEW ORLEANS JAMBALAYA.
MMM. IT'S GOT
A LOT OF BIG FLAVOR.
THAT'S GOOD SAUSAGE. I COULD
HEAR IT SNAP WHEN I BIT INTO IT.
REALLY GOOD.
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER, HE KNOWS HOW
TO MAKE THE GOOD STUFF.
AND HE'LL SMOKE
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
SMOKED MEATLOAF IS REALLY GOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA SMOKE THIS.
YES.
GROUND BEEF, 80-20.
80-20.
CAST OF CHARACTERS--
BARBECUE SAUCE.
HOUSE...
HE-HOUSE.
SEASONED BREADCRUMBS,
MILK...
THAT'S A LOT OF MILK.
ONION SOUP MIX...
EGGS.
WELL MIXED.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN OUR PAN HERE.
THE REASON YOU DO
THE LITTLE LOG
IS YOU DON'T LAY
THE WHOLE THING OUT.
IT'S REALLY GONNA GET
A NICE CRUST AROUND THAT.
YEAH.
LET THE SMOKE
TOUCH EVERYTHING IT CAN.
AND GET SOME BARK
ON IT.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA SMOKE?
FOUR HOURS.
WOW. LETS GO COOK THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
ONE FOR YOU, ONE FOR ME.
FOUR HOURS?
YEP.
CLOSE HER UP.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, THAT IS SUPER JUICY.
YUMMY.
YOU GOT TO SLICE THAT.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THE SMOKE RING
ON THAT.
A RIBBON OF BARBECUE SAUCE
ON THERE,
SOME GRILLED ONIONS
ON THERE.
NICE CALL.
DO YOU SEE THAT SMOKE RING?
BOY, THAT'S MOIST.
GREAT FLAVOR--
NOT OVERSMOKED, NOT TOO SWEET,
WITH A NICE LITTLE
SMOKED FLAVOR, DOWN HOME.
DO YOU MAKE THE MASH
AND THE GRAVY, TOO?
YOU BET.
EVERYTHING MADE SCRATCH?
YOU BETCHA.
GREAT MASHED POTATOES
AND GRAVY.
IS THAT COMFORT FOOD
OR WHAT?
THAT'S COMFORT FOOD
AT ITS BEST.
IT'S GOT A GREAT SMOKY FLAVOR,
DONE JUST RIGHT.
IT IS THE BEST MEATLOAF I HAVE
EVER HAD IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST PLACE YOU
CAN GO, DIAMOND IN THE ROUGH.
THIS IS TOP-NOTCH.
IT'S ALL ABOUT PAT'S.
DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER THAN
THAT. "IT'S ALL ABOUT PAT'S."
DID YOU THINK
IT WOULD BE THIS?
NOT AT ALL.
ONCE WE DISCOVERED
THIS PLACE,
NEVER WENT BACK
TO ANY OTHER PLACE.
I KNOW WHY THEY'RE LINED UP.
THERE'S SOME TEXANS THAT COULD
COME TAKE A LESSON UP HERE
IN SALT LAKE.
PAT'S HAS GOT IT
HANDS DOWN.
THIS IS IT?
THIS IS IT.
QUALITY PRODUCT, GOOD SERVICE
AND EVERYBODY LOVES THE JOINT.
YOU GOT YOUR GAME ON.
IT'S NUTS. IT'S GONZO.
IT'S UNHOOKED.
IT'S "OFF THE HOOK," PAT.
OFF THE HOOK.
UNHOOKED, OFF THE HOOK--
HELP US, NOW.
NEXT UP, MISSISSIPPI...
VERY GOOD, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT HITS YOUR TASTE BUDS.
WHERE THE NEIGHBORHOOD
FAVORITES...
HERE WE GO.
WHOA.
ARE FRESH FROM THE GULF.
MMM, WOW, LOOK AT THAT MEAT.
REALLY NICE.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
HERE ON TRIPLE "D" YOU EXPECT ME
TO ROLL TO PLACES
THAT ARE FUNKY.
WELL, SOMETIMES THE FUNK'S ON
THE INSIDE,
IN THE MENU, IN THE VIBE,
KIND OF LIKE THIS--THE BLOW FLY
HERE IN GULFPORT, MISSISSIPPI.
NOW THE ORIGINAL BUILDING
FROM 1961
WAS DESTROYED
IN HURRICANE KATRINA,
SO THEY REBUILT
ON 13-FOOT STILTS
AND GOT BACK TO COOKING
THE DOWN-HOME FOOD
THAT'S KEPT 'EM PACKED
FOR DECADES.
CHEF, CREOLE PASTA DINNER
FOR THIS BIG CHICKEN.
(man) ALL RIGHT.
MISSISSIPPI COASTAL CUISINE.
A LOT OF FRESH SEAFOOD.
CRAB CLAWS.
A SEAFOOD GUMBO.
IT JUST CAN'T BE BEAT.
HERE YOU ARE, SIR.
THIS IS AN INSTITUTION.
OH, YEAH.
PEOPLE HAVE GROWN UP
COMING HERE.
LIKE GULFPORT NATIVE
SCOTT WEINBERG
WHO JUMPED AT THE CHANCE TO OWN
A PIECE OF HIS CHILDHOOD.
I GOT A SHRIMP PO'BOY
COMING AT ME.
NOW DID YOU
CHANGE ANYTHING?
YOU DON'T FIX
WHAT AIN'T BROKEN,
YOU KNOW, SO WE CAME IN
AND PRETTY MUCH
LEFT EVERYTHING THE SAME.
HERE'S YOUR
RED BEANS AND RICE.
WHICH MEANS A MENU FILLED
WITH GULF COAST CLASSICS...
GOT SIX CRAB CAKES.
DONE WITH A BLOW FLY TWIST.
THAT...
LIKE STUFFING FLOUNDER
WITH CRAB CAKES.
PUTTING THE TWO TOGETHER--
I MEAN, DON'T YOU HAVE
TO HAVE A LICENSE TO DO THAT?
WE DO.
VERY, VERY GOOD.
AS YOU CAN SEE IT'S MADE
WITH JUMBO LUMP CRABMEAT.
NOW WHERE'S THE CRAB
COME FROM?
FROM HERE.
FROM HERE?
THIS IS FRESH
JUMBO LUMP CRABMEAT.
SO THEY'RE NOT FROZEN.
NO.
WE GOT GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
SO YOU GRIND THE BELL PEPPER
DOWN TO THE POINT
TO WHERE IT'S SO THIN
THAT ONCE IT GETS HOT,
IT ESSENTIALLY COOKS.
YEAH.
WE GOT ONIONS. ALL RIGHT,
THEN I HAVE SIX EGGS HERE.
THERE'S YOUR BINDER.
AND THEN YOU GOT
A LITTLE CELERY,
CREOLE SEASONING--
WE MAKE THAT HERE--
AND THEN YOU GOT
THE OLD BAY SEASONING,
PARSLEY, FRESH PARSLEY,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE CHICKEN BASE,
SEAFOOD BASE,
CREOLE MAYO, MAYONNAISE
AND ZATARAIN'S CREOLE MUSTARD.
I GOT TO PUT
THE GREEN ONIONS IN.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WHAT I'M GONNA DO
IS JUST MIX THIS UP.
JUST USE OUR HANDS.
WE'RE PRETTY INFORMAL.
DO YOU EVER MAKE BLENDER NOISES
WHEN YOU'RE DOING IT?
JUST FOR FUN.
YEAH, JUST FOR FUN.
(imitating blender)
SO THIS IS THE AMOUNT OF CRAB
TO THAT AMOUNT OF BREADCRUMBS?
YES.
I ALREADY LIKE THE WAY
WE'RE PLAYING BALL.
KIND OF LIKE TO FOLD THAT IN,
MAKE SURE IT'S NICE AND COATED
BEFORE I PUT
THE BREADCRUMBS IN.
HUH?
YOU SEE THIS TEAMWORK
RIGHT HERE?
OH, YEAH.
THIS IS SKILLED LABOR
FOR MY KIND.
THERE'S A JOB FOR YA
IF TV DOESN'T WORK OUT.
THERE IS. THIS IS--
WELL, THIS IS--
THIS ALL I REALLY KNOW
HOW TO DO ANYWAY.
NOW WE'RE READY TO STUFF
OUR FLOUNDER.
WE TAKE IT, CUT IT
RIGHT DOWN THE SPINE,
JUST KIND OF WORK YOUR WAY
DOWN THE BONES.
YOU CAN SEE THE RIB BONES
RIGHT THERE IN THE MIDDLE.
LITTLE BIT
OF CRAB CAKE MIX HERE
AND JUST GO RIGHT DOWN
THE CENTER LIKE THAT.
YOU WANT TO DRIZZLE
A LITTLE BUTTER ON IT.
YEAH, A LITTLE.
I WOULD HAVE BEEN SCARED
OF A LOT.
A LITTLE CREOLE SEASONING
RIGHT ON TOP.
AND THEN YOU WANT
TO PUT SOME WATER IN THERE
TO KEEP IT FROM
STICKING TO THE PAN.
ARE WE GOING IN FULL OVEN
OR JUST TOP?
CONVECTION OVEN.
WHAT TEMPERATURE'S THE OVEN?
IT'S AT 400.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THAT LONG?
YES.
HOLY MOLY.
HERE WE GO.
WHOA. OH.
HAVE AT IT.
LOOK AT THAT,
HOW JUICY. MMM.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT MEAT,
NICE, WHITE, FLAKY.
REALLY NICE.
OH, MAN, TENDER.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
A LOT OF FLOUNDER THERE.
IT'S LIKE A FLOUNDER
FOR A FAMILY.
VERY GOOD, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT HITS YOUR TASTE BUDS.
GOOD, FRESH, WELL-PREPARED FOOD
AROUND WONDERFUL
FUN-LOVING PEOPLE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THE TOUR.
HEY, "CAPTAIN FUNNY PANTS,"
WHO STUCK THE PLASTIC FLY
ON MY FOOD?
THAT'S A TRADITION HERE.
EVERY PLATE GETS A FLY ON IT.
THE FLIES.
'CAUSE COME SUMMER,
THE REAL LIFE BLOW FLY
IS JUST ABOUT THE LOCAL MASCOT.
HEY, THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE
TO DEAL WITH DOWN HERE.
BLOW FLY,
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE IN THE WORLD
PEOPLE GET MAD
IF THEY DON'T HAVE FLIES
ON THEIR FOOD--THE BLOW FLY INN.
AT THE END OF THE DAY,
PEOPLE COME FOR THE FOOD.
GUMBO?
RIGHT HERE.
AND HOW'S THE GUMBO?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S JUST REALLY
FRESHLY PREPARED.
BY HEAD CHEF TIM WILLIAM.
TODAY WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BLOW FLY GUMBO,
WHICH IS SAUSAGE
AND SEAFOOD GUMBO.
NO FLIES, THOUGH.
NO FLIES.
ADD A LITTLE BUTTER.
SO WE'RE GONNA SWEAT DOWN--
CALLED THE HOLY TRINITY.
ONIONS--UH-HUH.
CELERY, BELL PEPPER.
BELL PEPPER.
STIR THAT.
THEN WE ADD THE HERBS--DRY
BASIL, LITTLE OREGANO, THYME.
YOU'RE MAKING GOOD TIME.
CHEF TIM IS GONNA HAVE
THE GUMBO DONE IN THREE MINUTES.
DASH OF CAYENNE PEPPER.
THEN WE PUT A LITTLE GARLIC.
IT'S INTERNATIONAL VAMPIRE WEEK.
PUT A LITTLE MORE IN.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL PUT IT ALL IN.
THERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT, OKAY.
INTERNATIONAL VAMPIRE WEEK.
WE'LL ADD SAUSAGE.
LET THAT COOK.
CRUSHED TOMATOES,
SEAFOOD BASE.
THEN SOME
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
BIT OF TABASCO SAUCE.
SO A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
MM-HMM.
I'M GONNA TAKE
MY WATER HERE.
JUST KIND OF EYEBALL THAT
WATER--OOH, THERE WE GO.
SEAFOOD GOES IN NOW?
SHRIMP.
WHOA, THAT'S A LOT.
OYSTER.
HOW MANY IS THAT?
THREE DOZEN,
MAYBE FOUR DOZEN OF OYSTERS.
IT'LL PROBABLY COOK DOWN
FOR ABOUT A HALF AN HOUR.
LET IT COME TO A BOIL.
GATHER--PUT THE OKRA IN LAST.
THAT ALSO HELPS
TIGHTEN IT UP.
MM-HMM.
ABOUT ANOTHER HALF AN HOUR,
BRING IT TO BOIL.
IS SHE READY?
SHE'S READY.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
RICE ON TOP.
PASS ME A FLY, CAROLINE.
I'M GONNA LOSE MY JOB
IF I DON'T PUT A FLY ON HERE.
(chuckles)
MMM. OH, THAT'S NICE.
NOT SPICY AT ALL...
MM-HMM.
BUT A REAL NICE RICH FLAVOR.
I LIKE THAT.
HOW FAR ARE
WE FROM LOUISIANA?
50, 60 MILES
FROM LOUISIANA.
NO, ONLY ABOUT 3 FEET.
3 FEET? OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S THE FRESHNESS
OF THE SEAFOOD.
VERY MUCH LIKE
DOWN-HOME COOKING.
'CAUSE THAT'S WHAT THESE FOLKS
ARE EXPECTING.
RED BEANS AND RICE.
(man) RIGHT HERE.
DOESN'T GET MORE DOWN HOME
THAN THAT.
YOU ENJOY IT.
THEY'RE DOING THIS GULF CLASSIC
THE BLOW FLY WAY...
YEAH, WE CAN SIT HERE
A MINUTE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
NEED A CUP OF GUMBO.
IN GULFPORT, MISSISSIPPI...
(man) IT'S GOOD.
THE BLOW FLY INN
HAS BEEN A GO-TO PLACE
FOR BAYOU CLASSICS
FOR MORE THAN 45 YEARS.
CRAB CAKES.
THANK YOU.
WONDERFUL, FRIENDLY PLACE
TO GO EAT.
HAS SOME FEEL-GOOD FOOD.
GULF COAST COMFORT FOOD
LIKE SHRIMP PO'BOYS,
SEAFOOD GUMBO
AND THIS LONG-TIME FAVORITE.
RED BEANS AND RICE.
IT'S GREAT.
SO YOU GIVE A GREEN LIGHT
ON THE RED BEANS AND RICE.
ABSOLUTELY.
REALLY GOOD CAJUN FLAVOR--COMES
STRAIGHT OUT OF NEW ORLEANS.
NEW ORLEANS TRADITION AND WE
KIND OF BROUGHT IT OVER HERE.
START OUT WITH
YOUR RED KIDNEY BEANS.
THEY LOOK PINK.
YEAH, WELL, THEY'VE BEEN SOAKING
OVERNIGHT IN WATER.
SO YOU STARTED DRY.
YES.
WATER.
IS THAT BAYOU WATER?
IS THAT FROM OUT FRONT?
NO, WE DON'T USE THAT
TO COOK WITH.
WE ONLY PULL THE FISH
OUT OF IT.
WE GOT GREEN BELL PEPPER
AND ONION.
SO, WAIT A SECOND, OUT OF THAT
WHOLE BIG OLD THING OF BEANS,
YOU'RE GONNA TICKLE IT
WITH 1/4 CUP OF CELERY?
LITTLE BIT OF CELERY.
IT DOESN'T TAKE
A WHOLE LOT OF CELERY.
YOU DON'T WANT A BUNCH OF
VEGETABLES TAKING UP SPACE.
YEAH, I'M NOT ASKING
FOR A SALAD BAR,
BUT, I MEAN, COME ON.
THAT'S IT.
I THINK YOU'VE BEEN BIT
BY THAT FLY A FEW TIMES.
GRANULATED GARLIC, SALT,
CREOLE SEASONING--THAT'LL GIVE
IT A LOT OF FLAVOR THERE--
PLENTY OF THAT.
OKAY.
DON'T FORGET THE BAY LEAVES.
AH.
HOT SAUCE.
ALL OF IT?
YOU JUST TELL ME WHEN.
PRETTY GOOD--YEAH,
WE CAN SIT HERE A MINUTE.
PLENTY OF THAT IN THERE.
HELPS BEER SALES.
EXACTLY.
OH, YEAH.
NOW THE SAUSAGE.
YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TAKE A MINUTE AND INSPECT THIS.
OKAY.
YOU THINK YOU SHOULD PUT
THAT MUCH IN?
MAYBE YOU SHOULD JUST HOLD SOME
OVER HERE FOR--
JUST A LITTLE ON
THE SIDE FOR YA? OKAY.
WHERE'S THE SAUSAGE
COME FROM?
THIS IS MANDA SMOKED SAUSAGE
OUT OF LOUISIANA.
LET ME GET THIS.
GIVE IT A GOOD STIR.
HOW LONG WILL THAT
NEED TO COOK?
IT TAKES ABOUT TWO HOURS.
SO WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
LET'S GO FISH.
YEAH, WE'VE GOT THE CAR.
WE'RE RIGHT THERE ON THE WATER.
YOU CATCH ANYTHING
OUT THERE?
SURE YOU CAN. YEAH, ALL
KINDS OF FISH OUT THERE.
TROUT THIS TIME OF YEAR...
YEAH.
MMM.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW
THAT SAUSAGE RENDERS DOWN,
AND THE BEANS--
IF YOU COOK 'EM MUCH MORE,
THEY'RE GONNA LOSE
THEIR BEAN FORM.
YEAH, YEAH. YOU GOT TO KEEP
A CLOSE EYE ON 'EM.
GET YOU A NICE
BOWL OF IT HERE,
LITTLE BIT OF RICE
IN THERE,
AND THEN WE TAKE
THE SAUSAGE.
NOW THAT'S THE SAME SAUSAGE
WE PUT IN THERE?
EXACTLY.
MMM. WOW, THAT'S NICE.
CREAMY.
A LOT OF DEPTH OF FLAVOR.
WOW.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD, MAN.
WELL, THANK YA.
I GOT TO MAKE
SOME OF THAT. MMM.
IT'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH THE BEST.
OH, IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
YOU WANT TO COME BACK OVER
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
WE COME ABOUT
TWICE A WEEK.
Y'ALL ENJOY.
IT'S REALLY COMING HOME.
YOU GOT TASTE-A-VISION ON
AT HOME?
TRY THIS.
HUH? HUH?
YEAH, WHO'S YOUR BUDDY?
SO WAS THAT A MONEY ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
NOW WHAT'S THAT
OVER THERE?
OVER THERE
IN THAT OTHER YARD?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S OVER THERE.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT--IT JUST MOVED BY.