HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
IT EXPLODED.
THIS TRIP...
REGIONAL CLASSICS...
HERE'S AN ORDER OF HALUSKI.
(Guy)
IN ALBUQUERQUE.
BIG PLATE OF HOME COOKIN'.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
IT'S ALWAYS THE BEST.
(Guy)
NEW MEXICAN STYLE.
WHOO! I THINK I GOT THE WHOLE
JALA AND THE PENO.
IN NEW ORLEANS,
A LOCAL FAVORITE...
IT'S THE TYPICAL NEIGHBORHOOD
RESTAURANT IN NEW ORLEANS.
(Guy)
FOR LOCAL FAVORITES.
RICH, VERY FILLING, VERY GOOD.
WHAT MORE COULD YOU ASK FOR?
(Guy)
AND IN PITTSBURGH...
TURKEY SANDWICH, PLEASE.
(Guy)
A FAMILY JOINT...
HOME-COOKED FOOD.
(Guy)
DOING FAMILY RECIPES...
FRIED MUSH.
WHAT DO YOU PUT ON YOURS?
BUTTER AND SYRUP.
OR WHAT FOLKS
AROUND HERE GREW UP WITH.
WHO'S GETTIN' HALUSKI?
IT IS HOLY HALUSKI.
DEFINITELY.
I'M MAKIN' THIS
THIS WEEKEND WHEN I GET HOME.
ARE YOU?
YES, I LOVE IT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
WHEN YOU'RE IN NEW YORK CITY,
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO FIND,
SOME GOOD PIZZA.
AND WHEN YOU'RE IN THE SOUTH,
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKIN' FOR,
KILLER FRIED CHICKEN.
BUT HERE I AM IN ALBUQUERQUE,
SO WHAT AM I LOOKIN' FOR?
I'M LOOKING FOR SOME
REAL DEAL NEW MEXICAN FOOD,
LIKE HERE
AT CECILIA'S CAFE.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
IT'S ALWAYS THE BEST.
THEIR BREAKFASTS ARE AMAZING.
THE KIND OF NORTHERN
NEW MEXICAN FOOD YOUR
GRANDMOTHER WOULD HAVE MADE.
(Guy)
THANKS TO CECILIA BACA
WHO STARTED COOKING
WITH HER OWN GRANDMOTHER
WHEN SHE WAS A KID.
WHEN DID YOU START?
I WOULD SAY ABOUT 5 YEARS OLD,
I'M THE OLDEST OF 12.
BEING THE OLDEST, YOU HAD
TO LEARN HOW TO DO
A LOT OF STUFF REAL QUICK.
WE USED TO MAKE TORTILLAS
ON THE OLD WOOD STOVE.
(Guy)
NOT ANY MORE, BUT SHE'S STILL
MAKIN' 'EM FRESH.
THAT'S IT.
ORDER UP.
(Guy)
ALONG WITH JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING ELSE.
AND NOW I NEED TWO BURRITOS.
TWO CORN CHICKEN ENCHILADAS.
GREEN CHILE CHICKEN STEW,
IT'S A BIG NEW MEXICO DEAL.
(Guy)
SO IS STUFFED SOPAPILLAS.
IT'S A LOCAL THING,
IT'S A TYPE OF BREAD.
IT'S LIKE A FRIED BREAD, BUT
THIS IS A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT,
BECAUSE WE'RE GONNA
DEEP-FRY 'EM.
START WITH THE FLOUR,
PUT SOME DRY YEAST INTO IT.
SO THIS IS GONNA
TAKE SOME TIME TO PROOF.
YEAH, I GIVE 'EM
ABOUT FIVE, TEN MINUTES.
THEN WE JUST ADD SOME SALT.
NOW WITH THE MANTECA,
WE DON'T ADD THAT MUCH,
BECAUSE WE'RE ALREADY
DEEP-FRYING ALL THIS.
THIS IS JUST GONNA HELP
SEPARATE IT A LITTLE BIT,
MANTECA IS LARD.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF
BAKING POWDER AND WARM WATER.
SO YOU POUR A LITTLE IN,
KINDA FEEL WHERE YOU'RE AT,
MOVE IT AROUND.
UH-HUH.
I LIKE YOUR
MEASURING TECHNIQUES.
PRACTICE MAKES PERFECT.
NOW YOU'RE KINDA KNEADING IT
AND THEN ROLL IT IN A BALL
AND LET IT PROOF
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
I FEEL LIKE I'M DRIVING
A LITTLE MINI BUS.
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE GOING
RIGHT INTO BIG TORTILLA LAND.
NO, THIS IS
A LITTLE BIT THICKER.
I'M READY TO DEEP-FRY,
START FLIPPING SOME LARD
ON TOP OF IT.
DO WE WANT IT FLAT?
NO, WE WANT IT TO PUFF UP.
OH, IT IS PUFFING,
HOUSTON, WE HAVE PUFF!
DO I FLIP IT?
FLIP IT, ARE YOU READY
FOR ANOTHER ONE?
PLEASE.
OH, YOU'RE LIKE ROWING THE BOAT,
GET ON IT, SISTER.
WE'RE JUST GONNA OPEN THIS
AROUND, THEN WE STUFF IT.
(Guy)
WITH EVERYTHING
FROM BEANS AND RICE
TO THIS LOCAL FAVORITE.
HERE'S YOUR OTHER MACHACA PLATE.
BEEF MACHACA ON A SOPAPILLA,
VERY MEXICAN.
I'M GONNA MAKE SOME MACHACA,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
PEPPER, GARLIC.
GRANULATED.
AND THEN I GET OREGANO.
MEXICAN OREGANO.
WATER, HOW LONG
WE GONNA LET THIS COOK?
FOR SIX HOURS, THEN WE
THROW IT ON THE FLATTOP HERE,
ONIONS, SOME JALAPENOS.
HOLY JALAPENO, HOW MANY WE GOT
IN THERE, A WHOLE CARTON?
FRESH TOMATOES.
IT'S A 50/50 JALAPENO TO
MEAT RATIO AT THIS POINT.
IT HAS TO BE SPICY.
OKAY.
ADD CHEESE TO IT.
MMM, WHOO! I THINK I GOT
THE WHOLE JALA AND THE PENO.
THE MEAT'S SUPER TENDER,
TOMATOES, TOMATOES ARE PERFECT.
WHAT I LIKE THOUGH IS THE
NATURAL MOISTURES IN THERE.
THE BREAD IS LIGHT AND FLUFFY,
BUT IT'S GOT GOOD CHEW TO IT.
GOOD TEXTURE, MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
DID YOU SEE ME SWEAT?
I THOUGHT YOU LIKED SPICY.
UH-HUH,
OH, MY TONGUE'S ON FIRE.
IT'S VERY GOOD, IT'S VERY SPICY.
ALWAYS FRESH.
(Guy)
FROM CHIPS...
MORE CHIPS, PLEASE.
(Guy)
TO CHILE RELLENOS.
THIS IS HOMEMADE,
YOU CAN TASTE THE DIFFERENCE.
(Guy)
TO THE CHILE SAUCES
NEW MEXICO'S FAMOUS FOR.
CAN'T GET CHILE
ANYWHERE IN THE UNITED STATES
LIKE YOU CAN IN NEW MEXICO.
THEY GOT YOU THERE.
RED OR GREEN CHILE,
WHAT DO THEY WANT ON IT?
(Guy)
THE GREEN CHILE IS THE ONE
THAT THEY PICKED EARLIER.
THE RED HATCH IS THE ONE
THEY LEAVE ON, THEN THEY
PICK IT, THEN THEY DRY IT.
THE RED CHILE IS VERY,
VERY GOOD.
IT HAS A WONDERFUL FLAVOR.
HOW OFTEN DO YOU MAKE
THE RED CHILE SAUCE?
WE DO CHILE TWICE A DAY,
WE'RE GONNA ROAST IT.
SO THESE ROAST FOR WHAT,
FIVE MINUTES?
FIVE MINUTES.
THEN WHEN WE BRING THEM OUT,
WE JUST STEEP THEM
IN THE HOT WATER.
UH-HUH, FIVE, TEN MINUTES.
MEXICAN OREGANO,
A LITTLE GARLIC, A LITTLE SALT,
USE THE WATER FROM THE CHILE
BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE ALL
THE FLAVOR'S IN THERE, RIGHT?
EXACTLY.
THE SKINS AND THE SEEDS,
EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL.
EVERYTHING,
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
MULTIPLE LAYERS OF FLAVOR.
IT JUST HAS A GREAT CONSISTENCY.
(Guy)
WHATEVER IT'S ON.
THE CHILE IS EXCELLENT.
(Guy)
TAMALES, BURRITOS,
ENCHILADAS.
ENCHILADAS ARE VERY POPULAR.
(Guy)
AND A SCRATCH-MADE PULLED PORK
CALLED CARNE ADOVADA.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST PLACES
IN TOWN TO GET
THE CARNE ADOVADA.
MMM, IT EXPLODED,
THAT IS SO JUICY.
THAT'S LIKE PULLED PORK
GONE WILD!
OH, THAT'S GOOD,
IS THERE A SHOWER HERE?
WHEN YOU ORDER
THE CARNE ADOVADA,
YOU CAN GET THE APRON.
IT'S SO JUICY, YOU'LL JUST
GET IT ALL OVER YOUR CLOTHES.
CECILIA, WHERE WERE YOU WITH
THAT LITTLE TIDBIT OF INFO,
BEFORE I BIT INTO IT,
AND IT GOT ALL OVER ME?
IT'S REALLY, REALLY TASTY.
I NEED THE QUESADILLA
AND CHIMICHANGA.
THANK YOU.
FIRST-RATE CLASSIC
NEW MEXICAN.
THIS IS NEW MEXICAN FOOD,
IT'S TRADITIONAL.
THE CHICHARONES.
CHICHARONES IS BIG
HERE IN NEW MEXICO?
IT'S VERY BIG IN NEW MEXICO.
THE CHICHARONES THAT PEOPLE EAT
LIKE POTATO CHIPS...
THAT'S PORK RINDS, BABY.
THE FRIED PORK LIKE PORK RINDS.
YEAH, YEAH.
NO, NO.
THIS IS CHICHARONES.
NOW THIS IS PORK FAT
WITH MEAT BUT NO SKIN.
NO SKIN.
SKIN, TYPICALLY,
WHEN PEOPLE FRY THAT UP,
THEY CALL THAT CHICHARONES.
UH-HUH,
THEY'RE BOTH CHICHARONES
BUT THIS ONE HAS MEAT IN 'EM.
THIS IS THE WAY WE MAKE
OUR CHICHARONES.
I ADD A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
SO IT DOESN'T STICK
TO THE BOTTOM, SALT.
SO YOU'RE SAYING THAT
A CHICHARONE CAN BE DIFFERENT
FROM REGIONS?
FROM REGIONS, YEAH.
UH-HUH!
SO WE'VE HAD THESE DOWN
FOR WHAT, ABOUT 3 1/2, 4 HOURS?
FOUR HOURS.
OH, I THINK LIKE A SUNTAN LOTION
OUT OF THAT WOULD BE GREAT.
YOU WANNA WARM UP YOUR TORTILLA?
YOU SEE WHERE MY JOB ENDS UP,
TORTILLA WARMER.
I'VE NEVER HAD
A CHICHARONE BURRITO,
I CANNOT WAIT.
YOU WANT CHEESE ON IT?
PLEASE, HOWEVER YOU RECOMMEND.
RED OR GREEN CHILE?
TAKE ME TO THE RED NOW.
INTO THE SALAMANDER
TO MELT THE CHEESE.
IS THAT THE NUMBER ONE
SELLER HERE?
THAT AND THE CARNE ADOVADA.
LOOK AT THAT, ARE THEY ALWAYS
THE SIZE OF A SMALL FOOTBALL?
ALWAYS THAT SIZE.
WOW! YOU BITE INTO IT,
AND YOU GET A LITTLE
TENDER PIECE OF PORK
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
YOU GET A CRUNCHY THING.
THAT'S SURE IS
A DIFFERENT CHICHARONE
THAN I'VE EVER HAD.
THE ONLY THING THAT NEEDS
TO GO ALONGSIDE OF THAT,
A REALLY ICE-COLD BEER, WOW!
THE BEST, THE BEST.
NO QUESTION.
I WILL NOT EAT 'EM
ANYWHERE ELSE.
WHOA!
ANYTHING CECILIA MAKES
IS GOOD.
IT'S HOMEMADE,
IT'S FROM THE HEART.
ARE THESE IN SOPAS?
IT IS WHAT IT IS.
NOW YOU'RE USING MY LINES.
THIS IS VERY SIMILAR
TO MY GRANDMA'S.
A LOT OF PEOPLE THAT LEAVE
FROM HERE SAYS IT'S JUST LIKE
EATING AT GRANDMA'S HOUSE.
WHAT IF YOUR GRANDMA'S ITALIAN?
WELL, YOU KNOW, WE CAN DO
ITALIANO...
OH, HERE SHE GOES!
(Guy)
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' TO NEW ORLEANS.
WITH HER NAMIN' THE FOOD
AFTER STREETS.
THIS IS THE TROUT TCHOUPITOULAS.
CAPILOOPAS, CHOPILOOTIE.
DELICIOUS.
HERE IN NEW ORLEANS, THERE'S
PLENTY OF FAMOUS RESTAURANTS
THAT ARE JUST PACKED
WITH TOURISTS,
BUT IF YOU LIVE HERE,
YOU NEED YOUR OWN PLACES TO GO.
YOU KNOW, THAT THE
OUT-OF-TOWNERS DON'T KNOW ABOUT,
LIKE THIS JOINT, JOEY K.
IT'S THE TYPICAL NEIGHBORHOOD
RESTAURANT IN NEW ORLEANS.
YOU KNOW THE MENU BY THE DAYS?
GREAT DOWN HOME
COMFORTABLE FOOD.
PRICES ARE GOOD, FOOD'S GREAT.
THEY MAKE YOU FEEL WELCOME,
WHAT MORE COULD YOU ASK FOR?
PLUS THE OWNERS ARE REALLY
NICE PEOPLE, THEY'RE GREAT.
THEY'RE NICE PEOPLE?
(Guy)
THAT'D BE CINDY FARNET
AND HER HUSBAND SAM.
HAD YOU BEEN
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS?
NEVER EVER.
NO.
(Guy)
UNTIL '89 WHEN THEY
GOT A CHANCE TO RUN
THIS LOCAL LANDMARK
AND DECIDED, "HEY, WHY NOT?"
WE JUST WERE DRAWN INTO IT.
(Guy)
THEY MIGHT HAVE BEEN NEW
TO THE BIZ,
BUT AS NEW ORLEANS NATIVES,
THEY KNEW WHAT MATTERED.
KEEPING THE CUSTOMERS HAPPY.
(Guy)
WITH LOCAL FAVORITES.
RED BEANS AND RICE GOOD?
IT'S AWESOME.
I'D HAVE TO GO FOR THE
FRIED OYSTERS, NUMBER ONE.
THE SHRIMP PO-BOY.
(Guy)
ALL SERVED UP
BY HEAD CHEF DARREN SMITH,
KNOWN BY EVERYONE
AS CHEF SMITTY.
I'M MAKIN' A SHRIMP MAGAZINE.
(Guy)
NAMED FOR THE STREET JOEY K'S
HAS BEEN ON FOR DECADES.
HOW ARE YOU ENJOYING
THE MAGAZINE?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
SOME ARTICHOKES IN THERE,
VERY TASTY.
HOW DO WE START IT?
FLOUR, KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, GRANULATED GARLIC,
MIX 'EM UP.
NOW I'M ABOUT TO DREDGE SHRIMP
IN MY SEASONED FLOUR.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BUTTER TO MY PAN.
WE GOT SOME BUTTER
IN THERE, HUH, LOOKS LIKE
A HOT TUB OF BUTTER.
IT'S LIKE THE PUBLIC POOL
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
OH, YEAH, I'M ABOUT TO ADD
MY SHRIMP TO THAT NICE BUTTER.
SHRIMP INTO THE DEEP END.
LET THAT SAUTE
FOR A FEW MINUTES,
TURN THE SHRIMP OVER.
OKAY, THAT'S AN ABUNDANCE
OF BUTTER.
WE ADD ARTICHOKE HEARTS,
A LITTLE DICED HAM.
I LIKE THE LANGUAGE
YOU'RE SPEAKING.
WHITE WINE.
THE MEETING HERE IN FLAVOR TOWN
IS GOING REALLY WELL.
OH YEAH, THE SHRIMP,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
WHOO! JOHNNY MONSTER FLAVOR
JUST JUMPED IN.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
YOU CAN'T SAUTE IT TOO LONG
BECAUSE YOU'RE GONNA
TURN THOSE SHRIMP TOUGH, RIGHT?
OH YEAH, FRESH BASIL,
GREEN ONIONS,
AND A LITTLE CHOPPED GARLIC,
STIR THAT UP.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO THERE,
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THAT OVER?
ANGEL HAIR PASTA.
I LIKE THAT, SERVE IT UP.
HEY, WHERE YOU GOIN'
WITH THE REST OF THAT SAUCE?
OH...
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE FOOLIN'?
A LITTLE PARMESAN CHEESE,
OH YEAH.
MMM, OH, THAT'S NICE.
LET ME TELL YOU
THE 90 REASONS I LIKE THIS.
EVERY INGREDIENT
THAT WENT IN THERE, I DIG.
THE HAM, THE SHRIMP IN
NICE LITTLE BATTERING ON THERE.
NICE AND TENDER, BUTTER,
WHITE WINE, GARLIC.
MMM, YEAH.
CAN'T GO WRONG WITH THAT.
IT'S RICH, VERY FILLING,
IT'S GOOD, VERY GOOD.
IT WAS GOOD THAT YOU NAMED
THE STREET AFTER THIS DISH.
AND NOT JUST ONE.
NOW WE HAVE EGGPLANT NAPOLEON.
AS IN NAPOLEON AVENUE.
STACKS OF EGGPLANT
WITH SHRIMP AND CRAWFISH.
IT'S NOT A COMBINATION
YOU SEE EVERY DAY.
NO.
THIS IS THE TROUT TCHOUPITOULAS.
CHOPOLOUPAS, APPELOOTIE.
TULAPOTUMUS.
I CAN'T SAY THE NAME EITHER.
TCHOUPITOULAS.
AND TROUT WITH THE SHRIMP
AND THE CRAB MEAT.
THE SHRIMP IS EXCELLENT.
YOU'RE GETTING THE REAL TASTE
OF LOUISIANA SEAFOOD.
AND IT'S A GREAT PLACE TO GO
WHEN YOU JUST DON'T WANNA COOK
AND YOU JUST WANNA EAT.
IT'S A PLACE YOU CAN COME,
YOU CAN BE COMFORTABLE.
YOU WON'T BE DISAPPOINTED.
IT FEELS LIKE
THE LOCAL CORNER JOINT.
YEAH.
AS A LOCAL, YOU WANNA EAT
AT LOCAL PLACES.
IT'S JUST A GOOD PLACE
TO COME AND GET
ALMOST WHATEVER YOU WANT.
(Guy)
EVEN IF WHAT YOU WANT
ISN'T CLASSIC NEW ORLEANS...
WHO HAD THE ROAST BEEF?
(Guy)
LIKE CHICKEN FRIED STEAK,
LAMB SHANK, AND THIS ONE.
I'M HAVIN' THE BRISKET.
SLOW COOKED
AND A NICE FULL FLAVOR.
GONNA DO A BEEF BRISKET
BUT FIRST, I WANNA MAKE
A DRY RUB.
KOSHER SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
GENEROUS?
YEAH.
SO A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC?
YES, AND SOME WHOLE THYME,
SWEET BASIL, I'LL MIX THAT UP
REAL GOOD.
THIS HERE'S LIKE
A BARBECUE DRY RUB,
AND WE GOT THE BRISKET
WITH THE CAP ON.
IT'S GOT A BUNCH OF FAT
RUNNIN' THROUGH IT.
TONS OF FLAVOR, BUT IT HAS
TO BE COOKED LOW AND SLOW
TO GET THE CHANCE TO BREAK DOWN
ALL THAT CONNECTIVE TISSUE
WHICH MAKES A LOT
OF THE GREAT FLAVOR.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO WITH THIS?
PUT A LITTLE OLIVE OIL ON IT.
DO YOU RUB IT IN?
YEAH, RUB IT IN.
FLIP IT OVER,
COAT THE OTHER SIDE.
PUT IT ON A FLATTOP
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
SEAR IT?
YEAH, EACH SIDE.
PUT A NICE CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE OF IT?
YEAH, I'M GONNA HAVE TO
FLIP THE BEEF BRISKET OVER.
HEATIN' UP THE FAT.
ANYTHING GONNA GO IN THERE
WITH THAT?
ONION, BELL PEPPER,
I'M GONNA LIFT THIS UP.
THE FAT RENDERS
AND POURS OVER THE SIDE
AND MOISTURIZES IT?
YES.
I DIG IT.
AND THEN A LITTLE
SECRET HAM PASTE.
HAM PASTE?
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
JUST TO GET IT STARTED,
STEAM IT A LITTLE BIT
AS IT COOKS, AND THEN
YOU RENDER DOWN.
GET YOUR OWN FAT AND JUICE...
YES.
PUT SOME FOIL OVER IT?
LOCK IT DOWN ABOUT 350
FOR FOUR HOURS.
FOUR HOURS,
IT SHOULD BE FALLIN' APART.
LET'S SEE IT,
WOW, THAT'S HOT!
CUT IT FOR YOU.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
THAT YOU NEEDED A KNIFE.
YOU COULD HAVE JUST LOOKED
AT IT, AND IT WOULD HAVE
FALLEN APART.
LOOK AT IT, THAT IS TENDER,
WHOA! MMM, THAT'S TASTY, MAN.
YOU DIDN'T PUT ANYTHING ELSE
IN THERE AFTER I TALKED TO YOU?
NO, I DIDN'T.
LOOK AT THAT,
THAT BROKE DOWN REAL NICE.
THAT'S EXCELLENT FLAVOR,
NOT TOO SALTY,
STILL ENOUGH TEXTURE,
BECAUSE I HATE WHEN THEY COOK
TOO MUCH AND THERE'S NO TEXTURE.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
THERE YOU ARE.
AS WE SAY HERE,
IT TASTES LIKE MAMA'S.
I THINK THE WORLD OF THIS PLACE.
IT'S ONE OF THE
BEST RESTAURANTS IN THE CITY.
YOU CAN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT MAGAZINE STREET
WITHOUT ANYBODY SAYING
JOEY K's.
THEY MAKE YOU
FEEL LIKE YOU'RE FAMILY.
EVERY TIME THE DOOR OPENS,
YOU'LL SEE SOMEBODY WALK IN
THAT YOU KNOW.
YOU ALWAYS WANNA COME BACK.
YOU'RE HAVIN'
THE TCHOUPITOULAS.
DO YOU KNOW
HOW TO SPELL THAT?
I CAN.
YOU KNOW HOW I SPELL IT?
NO.
WRONG EVERY TIME.
(Guy)
NEXT UP, PITTSBURGH.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE,
IT'S SOMETHING YOU WOULD GET
FROM YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
YOU KNOW WHAT MUSH IS, POLENTA?
I KNOW WHAT POLENTA IS,
YOU CALL IT MUSH,
IN PITTSBURGH THEY DO.
AND WHAT DO YOU PUT ON YOURS?
BUTTER AND SYRUP.
ON POLENTA?
YEAH, IT'S A BREAKFAST.
THERE'S ALMOST NOTHING SCARIER
THAN TRYING TO OPEN
A RESTAURANT,
ESPECIALLY FOR SOMEONE
THAT DOESN'T HAVE ANY
FORMAL CULINARY TRAINING.
BUT THAT DIDN'T STOP
ONE FORMER WAITRESS
HERE IN PITTSBURGH.
TOOK OUT A SMALL LOAN
AND BOUGHT A LITTLE JOINT
IN A STRIP MALL
AND TURNED IT
INTO A NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE.
GOTTA CHECK OUT KELLY O'S.
TURKEY SANDWICH, PLEASE.
SO YOU'VE GOT YOUR OWN DINER
IN YOUR OWN BACKYARD.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
AND HOME-COOKED FOOD.
IT TASTE HOMEMADE,
IT TASTES LIKE MOM'S.
(Guy)
AND MOM'S KELLY O'CONNOR...
I'VE BEEN CALLED
KELLY O MY WHOLE LIFE.
KELLY-O-O-O.
(Guy)
WHO BOUGHT THIS PLACE
EIGHT YEARS AGO.
DID YOU SAY, "I'M JUST GONNA
OPEN UP MY JOINT
"AND START SERVING THINGS
I LIKE TO EAT?"
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
IT'S LIKE A FAMILY ATMOSPHERE.
(Guy)
AND THE WHOLE FAMILY'S
PITCHIN' IN.
YOU GOT YOUR DAUGHTER
WORKIN' HERE, YOU GOT
YOUR SON WORKIN' HERE.
YOUR MOM'S WORKIN' HERE.
THIS IS TOOTIE,
THIS IS KELLY'S MOM.
HI, NICE TO MEET YOU.
HI CAMERA.
(Guy)
IT'S HER COOKIN'
THAT GOT IT ALL STARTED.
FAMILY RECIPES HANDED DOWN.
(Guy)
LIKE FRESH BOLOGNESE,
ROAST TURKEY.
HOT MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
(Guy)
AND THIS PITTSBURGH FAVORITE.
HERE'S AN ORDER OF HALUSKI.
NOODLES, ONIONS, CABBAGE,
AND BACON.
IT'S A POLISH THING.
YOU CAN ASK ANY PITTSBURGH KID.
THEY KNOW WHAT THIS IS,
EVEN IF THEY'RE NOT POLISH.
YOU KNOW, PICNICS YOU GO
TO LITTLE FESTIVALS,
CHURCH FESTIVALS...
IT IS HOLY HALUSKI.
IT'S DEFINITELY HOLY HALUSKI.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN MAKING
THIS DISH?
MY WHOLE LIFE,
SOME BUTTER IN THERE.
SOME REGULAR ONIONS.
BOIL THE CABBAGE.
NO SALT IN THE WATER
OR ANYTHING?
NOPE.
NOTHING LIKE A HOT
WARM CABBAGE FACIAL.
OH, I AGREE.
EVER TRY THOSE IN THE MORNING?
I AGREE, IT'S GREAT FOR PORES.
AND THEN JUST CUT IT,
ARE YOU GONNA CUT IT FOR ME?
WHATEVER YOU WANT ME TO DO,
SUNSHINE.
JUST JULIENNE IT,
YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
PUT IT RIGHT IN THERE.
IN THE POOL?
YEP, IT'LL CARAMELIZE,
IT'LL TURN LIKE BROWN, YOU KNOW.
DIG IT.
GARLIC SALT, BACON,
LOTS OF BACON.
HOW MUCH GOES IN HERE?
TEN OUNCES OF COOKED,
CHOPPED BACON.
THAT STARTED OUT PROBABLY
AS ABOUT A POUND AND SOMETHING.
YES.
I'M ALREADY LIKING
WHAT I'M SEEING.
ONCE YOU HAVE IT,
YOU WON'T FORGET IT.
SO SOME EGG NOODLES
THAT ARE COOKED AL DENTE.
YOU GOT IT.
THAT'S A NICE RATIO OF CABBAGE
AND ONIONS AND NOODLES,
STIR THIS ALL AROUND?
YEP, YOU LIKE CABBAGE?
I LOVE CABBAGE.
THE DARKER IT GETS,
THE BETTER IT GETS.
OH YEAH, SEE THAT,
THAT RIGHT THERE.
YES, THAT'S CRISPY,
THAT'S THE WAY IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE, RIGHT, LIKE THAT?
YOU WANT SOME PEPPER,
IS THIS READY?
YEP.
HERE'S A LITTLE ROMANO.
GET A HILL OF IT ON THERE.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I WOULD
WANNA EAT EVERY DAY.
REALLY?
I'M MAKING THIS WEEKEND
WHEN I GET HOME.
ARE YOU?
I LOVE IT, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE CABBAGE FOR BITTERNESS,
SWEETNESS OF THE ONION,
THE SALTINESS OF THE BACON.
I'M HAVING A "HALUSKINATION."
THAT'S ONE OF THE SURPRISE
DISHES I'VE HAD ON "TRIPLE D."
MOM, I FOUND A NEW HALUSKI,
DON'T BE MAD.
SHE'S GONNA SPANK
YOUR CABOOSKIE
WHEN SHE FINDS OUT
YOU LOVE THIS HALUSKI.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
I LOVE IT ALL.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE,
IT'S SOMETHING YOU'D GET
FROM YOUR GRANDMOTHER.
(Guy)
OR KELLY O'S GRANDMOTHER.
HOME COOKING
THAT KEEPS THESE FOLKS
PACKIN' IN.
HOT TURKEY GRAVY SANDWICH,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
MEATLOAF SANDWICH, IT'S PROBABLY
ONE OF THE BEST IN TOWN.
SAUSAGE OMELET
WITH REGULAR HOME FRIES.
THEY MAKE POTATOES
LIKE MY DAD DID.
(Guy)
AND THIS ONE.
FRIED MUSH.
(Guy)
THE WAY KELLY'S MOM MADE IT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT MUSH IS,
POLENTA?
I KNOW WHAT POLENTA IS,
YOU CALL MUSH?
LET'S GET IT GOIN',
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
YOUR POLENTA,
I'M IN THE STIRRING MODE.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO MAKE MOTOR BOAT SOUNDS?
YEAH.
I'M IN THIRD GEAR.
OVERDRIVE.
JUST STIR IT,
STIR IT AGAIN REALLY THICK
AND THEN YOU LOAF PAN IT.
COOL DOWN.
YEP, SLICE IT,
DEEP-FRY IT, OR GRILL IT?
ONE DEEP-FRIED
AND ONE FLATTOP.
HOW LONG DOES YOUR GO
OVER HERE?
UNTIL IT'S CRISPY.
NOW WHAT DO YOU
PUT ON YOURS?
BUTTER AND SYRUP.
BUTTER AND SYRUP ON POLENTA?
YEAH, IT'S A BREAKFAST.
YOU'RE LAUGHIN'.
I AM, I'M SCARED OF THAT.
OH WOW!
WHAT?
DON'T PUT THAT ON MINE,
I'M PUTTIN' SYRUP ON MINE.
JUST A LITTLE TINY
BABY TASTE WITH SYRUP.
QUIT IT.
DO YOU PUT SYRUP ON PIZZA?
MY KIDS LIKE IT.
THIS IS HOW YOU GET IT GOIN'.
SOME BACON, MMM.
OH NO... WAY BETTER.
WAY BETTER.
(Guy)
AND SHE'S SERVIN' IT UP
FOR LUNCH, A LITTLE CREAMIER
BUT NO SYRUP.
THIS ONE GETS HOMEMADE
BOLOGNESE SAUCE.
VEAL, GROUND CHUCK,
AND SWEET SAUSAGE.
YEAH, I THINK WHEN I DRIVE UP
AND SEE IT SAY KELLY O'S
OUT FRONT,
I'M EXPECTING THERE
TO BE VEAL IN THE BOLOGNESE,
LOOK AT THAT.
HOLD ON GUY,
YOU'RE GETTIN' A BIG PLATEFUL.
HEY, THAT'S ENOUGH,
THAT'S ENOUGH.
AH, PECORINO ROMANO CHEESE
ON TOP.
AH, DELICIOUS.
THE POLENTA, NICE AND CREAMY.
THE BOLOGNESE GOT
SOME NICE BIG CHUNKS OF MEAT.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
IT IS A LOT OF POLENTA.
THE MEAT SAUCE IS THE BEST.
I LOVE IT.
WOW!
IT'S A NICE TWIST
ON THE PASTA.
TO COME IN AND FIND
THAT I CAN GET SOME POLENTA,
FRESH MADE BOLOGNESE,
OR I CAN HAVE IT FRIED
AND PUT SYRUP ON IT, IS GREAT.
SO FAR TODAY, I'VE BEEN
TO POLAND AND ITALY.
UP NEXT, TURKEY.
DO YOU MAKE TURKEY POT PIE?
YES, IT'S A SOUP.
IT'S A SOUP?
YEAH.
YOU DON'T FIND THAT
IN MANY PLACES.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
I NEED THE MASHED POTATOES.
(Guy)
AT KELLY O'S DINER
IN PITTSBURGH,
KELLY O'CONNOR IS SERVING UP
ALL KINDS OF LOCAL FAVORITES.
PEOPLE LIKE HALUSKI
IN PITTSBURGH.
POLENTA, IT'S INCOMPARABLE
TO ANYBODY ELSE'S
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
TWO ORDERS OF HOME FRIES.
(Guy)
NOT BAD FOR A COOK WHO GOT
HER TRAINING TOTALLY ON THE JOB.
YOU TAUGHT YOURSELF?
YES.
STARTIN' WITH FAMILY RECIPES.
SOMETHING YOU'D ALMOST GET
AT YOUR HOUSE.
BEST THING ON THE MENU,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
TURKEY POT PIE SOUP.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
(Guy)
KELLY CAME UP WITH THIS ONE
HERSELF AND FOLKS HERE LOVE IT.
IT'S THE BEST SOUP.
SO WHAT IF WE
SPICE IT UP A LITTLE?
OH, WHAT'S IN THIS
LITTLE BASKET OF MAGIC?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF A DRY RUB.
A LITTLE SEASONING SALT,
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY,
BASIL, THAT WON'T HURT US,
PAPRIKA, GARLIC POWDER,
A LITTLE POULTRY SEASONING,
AND NOW, MIX UP THAT DRY RUB.
I DON'T DE-BLING
JUST FOR EVERYBODY.
NOW YOU GET UP UNDERNEATH
THAT TURKEY SKIN LIKE THIS.
SEE HOW THAT SEASONING
IS ALL SITTING ON THE MEAT,
SO THAT FAT WILL RENDER DOWN
AS IT COOKS AND FLAVOR
ALL OF THAT MEAT.
I'LL GO AHEAD AND THROW SOME
ONIONS DOWN IN THERE,
SOME CARROTS IN THERE,
WRAP IT IN FOIL.
WE DON'T WANNA LOSE ALL THAT
MOISTURE OUT OF THE TURKEY.
THEN REST 3 1/2 HOURS.
GET IT NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN,
DE-BONE IT.
TAKE OFF THE TURKEY BREAST,
YOU CAN USE THAT
FOR THE SANDWICHES.
CORRECT.
BOIL OFF THE CARCASS.
WITH ALL OF THE VEGGIES
THAT WE ROASTED,
WE'LL SIMMER THIS
IN A BUNCH OF WATER.
GET A LITTLE FLAVOR
IN THE BROTH, STRAIN IN.
NOW WE'RE LEFT
WITH OUR TURKEY STOCK.
I ADD THE CELERY AND ONIONS.
HOW LONG'S THIS GONNA SIT THERE
AND SIMMER?
TEN MINUTES.
NOW, READY FOR THE POTATOES.
FROZEN VEGETABLES IN.
THAT'S A HEAPIN' HELPIN', HUH,
GIVE IT TO YOU
ON THE FROZEN VEGGIES THING,
BECAUSE THAT'S KINDA
WHAT PEOPLE EXPECT.
ALL THE TURKEY
THAT WE PICKED FROM THE BONES,
WE'LL MAKE A LITTLE ROUX.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO DOWN,
THAT'S THICKENING UP.
I MEAN, THAT'S JUST
MY TWO CENTS.
I LIKE YOUR TWO CENTS.
LOOK AT ALL THE LOVE
YOU GOT IN THAT.
LOOKS GOOD.
HOMEMADE PIE CRUST.
MMM, THAT IS CREAMY GOODNESS
RIGHT THERE,
BUT IT'S NOT STICKY
LIKE CANNED SOUP.
ALL THAT GREAT TURKEY AND THEN
YOU'VE GOT ALL YOUR VEGGIES.
PEOPLE CAN SAY
WHATEVER THEY WANT
ABOUT THE FROZEN VEGGIES,
BUT THEY'RE NICE AND TENDER.
THAT CRUST IS MONEY, I MEAN
THAT TASTES LIKE A BAKED...
POT PIE.
YEAH, THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
TURKEY POT PIE DINNER.
THANK YOU.
HOW IS IT TODAY?
VERY GOOD.
I'M WORKIN' FOR THE COMPLIMENT.
YEAH, WE GO FOR GOOD FOOD.
GOOD FORTUNES, GOOD FOOD.
IT'S ONE OF THOSE
LITTLE OUT-OF-THE-WAY PLACES.
SO IT REALLY IS
A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT.
THAT'S THE BEST PART
ABOUT IT.
THIS IS WHY YOUR PLACE
IS SO COOL.
IT'S A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
WORKING REALLY HARD WHO HAVE
A TON OF ENTHUSIASM.
I'M PROUD OF MYSELF.
YOU SHOULD BE, YOU'RE MAKIN'
THINGS FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S HOMEMADE,
THAT'S ALWAYS REALLY GOOD.
EVERYONE'S FAMILY HERE.
YOU'RE KILLIN' IT,
WHAT A COOL PLACE!
WELL, IT'S REALLY HARD
TO GET TO WHERE I'M AT.
AND LOOK AT IT, I HAVEN'T SEEN
A PERSON WALK OUT OF HERE
WITHOUT A SMILE.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED FOR SOME MORE
GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
NO, MINE'S NATURALLY BLOND,
TOOTIE.
NO, IT ISN'T, I SEE YOUR ROOTS.
NO, NO, I DYE MY ROOTS BROWN
JUST TO KINDA BE IN
WITH THE IN-CROWD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?