I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
BEEN IN THE FAMILY
FOR 60 YEARS.
LONG-TIME LEGENDS.
MY FAMILY USED TO COME HERE
AS I WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
SANDWICH à LA CARTE,
OR A DINNER PLATE...
(man) THANK YOU, MY FRIEND.
ROASTIN' AND SLICIN'
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
STEP UP, STEP IN,
COME IN AND WIN.
AND FOLKS KNOW WHEN TO SHOW UP
FOR WHAT THEY WANT.
FRIDAY, I KNOW
IT'S SALMON.
SUNDAYS AND THURSDAYS--
LAMB SHANK DAYS.
WOW.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
IN OMAHA...
3,000 FISH A WEEK?
CORRECT.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN LOVIN' CARP
SINCE THE '30s.
DROVE ALL THE WAY FROM
FLORIDA TO EAT THIS FISH.
NOT SOMETHING
YOU CAN GET EVERYWHERE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
AND THEY'LL DO
ANYTHING WITH IT.
NICE PICKLING.
TASTES LIKE PICKLE
WITH A SUSHI FEEL.
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
FRIED CARP DINNER.
AND IN PITTSBURGH...
SPAGHETTI WITH MEATBALLS
AND MARINARA.
THE SAUCE IS REALLY RICH.
31 YEARS
OF BIG FOOD...
MMM.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND BIG FLAVOR.
MMM. OH, THAT'S GOOD.
AT A PLACE
CALLED BIG JIM'S.
RESTAURANTS LIKE THIS THAT
HAVE BEEN AROUND FOR A LONG TIME
ALWAYS MAKE IT
THE WAY WE LIKE IT.
ONE MORE BITE,
AND THEN I'LL GO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN I ROLL INTO SAN FRAN
FOR A CONCERT OR A GAME
OR JUST HANGING OUT
WITH THE CREW,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES TO GO
IS THIS--TOMMY'S JOYNT.
IT'S BEEN A LOCAL NEIGHBORHOOD
FAVORITE FOR OVER 60 YEARS,
DEFINITELY ONE OF MINE,
AND YOU ARE SO GONNA DIG THIS.
STEP UP, STEP IN,
COME IN AND WIN.
IT'S A GERMAN HOFBRAU,
AND IT'S LIKE ECLECTIC.
WHERE YOU CAN GET
ROAST BEEF...
(woman) TURKEY
SANDWICH.
PASTRAMI.
(woman) SLICED
IN FRONT OF YOU.
THIS IS LIKE
AN OASIS.
(Guy) IT IS.
PASTRAMI, BRISKET, HAM,
CORN BEEF, TURKEY,
ROAST BEEF...
SANDWICH à LA CARTE,
OR A DINNER PLATE.
(man) THANK YOU, MY FRIEND.
AND THEY'VE BEEN DOING IT
THIS WAY SINCE '47.
TOMMY HARRIS
WAS A RADIO STAR,
WANTED TO BE
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
SO HE OPENED UP
THIS JOINT.
WE'LL CUT THAT FOR YOU.
MADE IT LOOK
JUST LIKE THIS.
AND A FEW YEARS LATER,
HIS COUSIN BILLY AND BILLY'S
WIFE TOOTSIE JOINED IN.
IT'S BEEN THE THE FAMILY
FOR 60 YEARS.
MY GOODNESS.
NOW TOOTSIE'S DAUGHTER SUZIE'S
KEEPING THE TRADITION ROLLING.
I'VE GOT MY TWO SONS SAM
AND ZACH WORKING HERE WITH ME.
ZACH BEHIND THE BAR.
WE GOT A COUPLE BEERS.
SAM OVER HERE.
TURKEY PLATE.
SAME EVERYTHING--
SAME BEEF, SAME TURKEY,
THE SAME STEWS. THAT'S WHAT
THE JOYNT IS ALL ABOUT.
THE MEATS THEY COOK
ARE TOP-NOTCH.
(man) OH, MY GOD,
THAT LOOKS SO GOOD.
FRESH-ROASTED EVERY DAY
DOWN IN THE BASEMENT...
I WONDERED WHERE
THE FOOD CAME FROM.
BY KITCHEN MANAGER
ELISEO OROZCO AND HIS CREW.
HOW MANY YEARS
YOU BEEN DOING THIS?
35.
NOW THE CORNED BEEF--THESE
ALREADY COME WITH BRINE ON 'EM.
I PUT A LITTLE MORE.
A LITTLE MORE JUNIPER BERRY,
A LITTLE BAY LEAF.
AND THEN THEY'RE GONNA
GO IN THIS POT?
RIGHT, GO IN THIS POT.
FOR HOW LONG?
THREE HOURS AND A HALF.
JUST WATER.
IS IT DONE?
YES.
(whistles)
LOOK HOW MUCH IT SHRINKS UP.
GIVE ME A SLICE OF THAT BAD BOY.
SEE? LOOK AT THAT--
ALL THAT FAT MARBLED IN THERE.
MMM.
NOT TOO SALTY,
BUT SUPER TENDER.
JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
PHENOMENAL.
THE ROAST BEEF
SANDWICH, PLEASE.
I'VE HAD THE ROAST BEEF
MORE TIMES THAN ANY OTHER.
HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU GO THROUGH A DAY?
THREE.
THREE OF THESE?
AS AN AVERAGE,
THREE OF THESE.
WHAT DO YOU CALL THIS?
I CALL IT STEAMSHIP ROUND.
WE CALL IT TOP ROUND
BEFORE BEING COOKED.
AFTER BEING COOKED,
IT'S ROAST BEEF.
OKAY.
FIRST INGREDIENT
IS SALT.
CAN I DO THIS?
YES.
I JUST WANT TO DO A LITTLE BIT,
AND THE REASON WHY...
YEAH?
IS THAT I JUST HAVE TO SAY
THAT I WAS AT TOMMY'S
AND I SEASONED
THE ROAST BEEF.
OKAY. YOU NEED
THE PEPPER.
OH, AND I'M GONNA
DO THAT?
OH, YEAH.
OH, I DIDN'T KNOW
I GET TO GO--
YOU HAVE TO--
THE WHOLE THING.
I BLESS YOU.
PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
OKAY.
MIGHT BE EVEN READY.
WRONG DAY TO WEAR FLIP FLOPS
IN THE KITCHEN!
WOW. CAN I GET THOSE
TO GO?
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW YOU TELL ME
WHICH PIECE YOU LIKE.
LET'S GO FROM THERE.
LOOK AT THAT PIECE.
GET A NICE LITTLE...
WOW.
MMM.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK YOU SHOULD
WEIGH A LOT MORE.
OH, THERE'S SOMETIMES
I LIKE ROAST BEEF
BETTER THAN PRIME RIB--
IT GOT FLAVOR,
IT'S TENDER, JUST--
JUST VERY TASTY.
VERY GOOD.
I DON'T EVEN NEED TO SAY
WHY I LIKE IT. YOU COVERED IT.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
PERFECT.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING,
SUNSHINE?
TURKEY SANDWICH.
(Guy) FRESH ROASTED TURKEY
SLICED IN FRONT OF YOU
ON A SOURDOUGH ROLL
FOR $5.50?
THAT'S RIGHT.
(Guy) IS THIS CRAZY?
$5.50?
YEAH, IT'S GOOD.
HOW BIG OF A TURKEY
IS THIS?
28-POUNDER.
I COULD WORK OUT
WITH THIS GUY.
SO WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
WITH THESE GUYS?
SEASON IT WITH A LITTLE
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
THAT'S IT--NOTHING IN
THE CAVITY, NO OTHER SEASONINGS?
NO, NO, NOTHING MORE.
INTO THE OVEN.
JUST PLAIN AND SIMPLE.
ARE THEY DONE?
IT IS DONE, YES.
(whistles)
THAT'S A BIG BIRD BONANZA.
LOOK AT THOSE THINGS.
CAN I HAVE A SLICE?
A LITTLE DARK MEAT, TOO.
LOOK AT THAT. SO YOU MAKE
THE GRAVY FROM SCRATCH?
YES.
MMM.
THAT'S TENDER TURKEY...
YEAH.
NOT DRIED OUT. I'VE BEEN
IN FANCY RESTAURANTS
THAT DON'T MAKE THINGS
NEARLY AS GOOD AS THIS.
OH, I GOTTA TAKE--
I GOTTA WALK AWAY FROM THAT.
TOMMY'S JOYNT IS KNOWN FOR GOOD
DEALS, GREAT BEERS, GREAT FOOD.
DONE FROM SCRATCH,
JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
THE CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE,
PORK SPARE RIBS,
A KILLER MEATBALL SUB...
MMM. IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND CHILI DONE THEIR WAY
FOR 33 YEARS.
FIRST TIME I EVER SAW IT
ON A MENU. I HAD TO TRY IT.
SO THIS IS BUFFALO MEAT?
BUFFALO MEAT, AND THEN
WE PUT THE SPICES ON.
GRANULATED ONION.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
WHITE PEPPER, A LITTLE
CUMIN IN HERE.
CHILI POWDER.
CHILI POWDER,
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE CAYENNE PEPPER,
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
WOW, THAT'S A LOT
OF WORCESTERSHIRE.
THEN WE PUT...
AHA.
A LITTLE CHERRY WINE
ON HER.
DROPS OF HOT SAUCE.
KETCHUP. I LIKE IT.
BOIL EVERYTHING TOGETHER,
THEN WE PUT THE BEANS,
AND READY TO EAT.
SEE WHAT YOU THINK.
MMM. SO IT'S NICE AND THICK.
NOT TO SPICY.
IT'S NOT TOO TOMATOEY.
GOOD TEXTURE TO THE MEAT.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT CHILI.
GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
SAME KIND OF FOOD
ALL THE WAY THROUGH THE YEARS.
AND THE SAME SPECIALS
EVERY DAY OF THE WEEK.
FRIDAY I KNOW IT'S SALMON.
MONDAY'S OXTAIL.
SUNDAYS AND THURSDAYS--
LAMB SHANK DAYS.
THEY DO THE BEST
IN THE CITY.
SPECIAL OF THE DAY--
LAMB SHANKS.
HERE WE GOT THE LAMB SHANKS.
OKAY.
WE ADD A LITTLE
GARLIC IN HERE.
A LITTLE BIT MORE, BECAUSE WE
NEED A GOOD FLAVOR TO COME OUT.
THEN WE GOT A LITTLE ONION,
WHITE PEPPER,
BUT LESS THAN THE OTHER BECAUSE,
YOU KNOW, WHITE PEPPER--
'CAUSE YOU'RE NOT TRYING
TO MAKE IT HOT.
THEN WE DO A PINK SALT,
THEN WE DO A NITTY-GRITTY.
THE NITTY-GRITTY?
OH, YES. THE NITTY-GRITTY
MEANS WINE.
IF WE DON'T HAVE
THE NITTY-GRITTY,
I MEAN, YOU'RE GOING
TO BE IN TROUBLE.
WE ADD A LITTLE WATER FOR--
NOT TO GET US STUCK ON THE PAN.
SO HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA GO FOR?
NO MORE THAN
THREE HOURS.
AND WITH THIS HALFWAY DONE,
WE DROWN IT IN SAUCE.
WHAT'S THE BASE
OF THE SAUCE?
THE STOCK OF THE LAMB.
OH, SO THE DRIPPINGS THAT WERE
GOING ON WITH THE LAMB--
RIGHT.
LOOK AT THOSE.
DO YOU WANT TO TASTE
ONE OF THOSE?
NO.
NO, HUH?
I WANT TO TASTE 'EM ALL.
OH.
OKAY, LET'S GET ONE.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S SAVORY.
IT'S ROASTED DOWN.
IT FALLS APART.
THERE'S TONS
OF FLAVOR IN IT.
THIS IS THE ONE TO COME FOR.
WOW. THAT'S DELICIOUS.
I'M LOVING
THE LAMB SHANK.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
(woman) IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN GOOD FOOD.
GREAT MENU.
JUST ENJOYING IT.
I'VE EATEN HERE MORE TIMES
THAN ANY OTHER RESTAURANT.
ONE OF THE BEST PLACES IN
SAN FRAN, DON'T YOU THINK?
ABSOLUTELY.
I DON'T THINK IT GETS
MUCH BETTER THAN THAT.
AND, OH,
LET'S NOT FORGET--
THE SAME PRICES...
YES.
SINCE, LIKE, 1962.
WELL, NOT QUITE,
BUT CLOSE.
PEOPLE ARE GONNA COME
TO SAN FRANCISCO AND SAY,
"HEY, I'VE BEEN
TO TOMMY'S JOYNT.
ISN'T THERE A GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE
HERE, TOO?"
NEXT UP...
ONCE YOU GET THE FIRST BITE,
YOU KNOW, IT SURPRISES YOU.
WE'RE HEADING TO OMAHA...
JEEZ!
AND IF YOU'RE THINKING BEEF...
3,000 FISH A WEEK?
CORRECT.
THINK AGAIN.
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
FRIED CARP DINNER.
SO HERE I AM DRIVING SMACK DAB
THROUGH THE MIDWEST--
OMAHA, NEBRASKA, TO BE EXACT.
YOU KNOW, THE LANDLOCKED STATE?
AND THEN I FIND THIS PLACE,
FAMOUS FOR THEIR FRESH FISH.
AT JOE TESS, THEY SERVE MORE
THAN 500 POUNDS OF FISH A DAY,
AND THEIR BIG HITTER--
FRIED CARP.
(man) TWO FISH...
IT'S MY ABSOLUTE
FAVORITE FOOD.
THREE FISH SOFT.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU CAN GET EVERYWHERE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
(man) HOW ABOUT 12 MORE?
DROVE ALL THE WAY FROM FLORIDA
TO COME AND EAT THIS FISH.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
ISN'T THIS, LIKE,
THE LAND OF BEEF?
NOT IN SOUTH OMAHA.
NOT SINCE THE '30s,
WHEN JOE TESS
STARTED SERVING UP
THE LOCAL CATCH.
(man) RIGHT THERE.
NOW DEEP FRIED CARP'S
A PIECE OF HISTORY
FOLKS KEEP COMING BACK FOR.
MY FAMILY USED TO COME HERE
AS I WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
I GREW UP ON IT.
OH, I'VE BEEN BRINGING HIM HERE
SINCE HE WAS A LITTLE KID.
ALWAYS BRING THE MEMORIES BACK
WHEN WE WERE KIDS,
AFTER BASEBALL GAMES, THIS IS
WHERE DAD WOULD WANT TO GO.
ALMOST LIKE AN INSTITUTION.
THAT'S IT EXACTLY.
KEPT ALIVE BY DAN FALT...
HERE'S A NICE ONE.
AND BROTHERS BILL AND DAVE.
ANOTHER STACK OF CARP.
THEY'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR YEARS.
SO HAS THE STAFF,
LIKE VETERAN DARRELL RYTYCH,
WHO'S BEEN HERE
SINCE '67.
JEEZ!
3,000 FISH A WEEK?
CORRECT.
AND THE CARP'S
BROUGHT IN FRESH
FROM LAKES
ALL OVER THE MIDWEST.
THE MAN AND HIS CARP.
CAN YOU HEAR
THEM BONES CRACKIN'?
OH, YEAH, YOU CAN.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER
SEEN A FISH CUT LIKE THAT.
CARP'S PROBABLY THE ONLY ONE
THAT HAS THE LITTLE WIDE BONES.
BECAUSE OF THE WAY
WE'RE SCORING LIKE THAT,
IT'LL COOK HOT ENOUGH
TO COOK THOSE OUT?
CORRECT,
BUT THEY GOTTA MAKE SURE WHEN
THEY PUT THE BREADING IN THERE,
THEY BREAD SO THEY
OPEN UP LIKE LITTLE FINGERS
AND THEY'LL FRY UP. FIRST CUT
I MAKE IS I CUT OFF THE TAIL.
THEN THERE'S THE RIB
SECTION IN THERE.
PICK THE ONE YOU WANT.
DOUBLE RIB.
ALWAYS THE RIB.
YOU GO TAIL AND RIB,
OR STRAIGHT UP RIB?
JUST RIBS.
THE TAILS OVER THE RIBS,
'CAUSE THEY GOT
A LITTLE MORE MEAT ON 'EM.
SO NOW WE MAKE THE BATTER.
SO GIVE US A RUNDOWN.
STARTING WITH
THE WHEAT FLOUR,
CORN FLOUR.
BOTH FLOURS USED A LOT
IN DREDGING.
YEAH. BAKING POWDER,
BAKING SODA, SOME WHEY.
WHEY, WHEY, WAIT, WAIT...
DEXTROSE, AND A LITTLE
SALT FLAVORING.
SALT FLAVORING?
YES.
ALL RIGHT,
THERE WE GO.
LET'S BREAD UP
A RIB AND A TAIL.
A LITTLE MORE SEASONING.
AND WHAT IS THAT?
SPECIAL SEASONING.
SALT AND PEPPER.
WHOA!
WE'RE GONNA FLOUR IT UP
SO THE FLOUR GETS--
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE
TICKLING IT.
IT'S THE TICKLE TECHNIQUE.
SCRATCH YOUR FINGERS
ACROSS THOSE SCORE MARKS
SO THE FLOUR GETS
IN THE SCORE MARKS.
KIND OF LOOKS LIKE
A LOBSTER TAIL.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
THE NEBRASKA LOBSTER?
DON'T LET ANYBODY TELL YOU
IT'S A CARP TAIL.
JUST RIGHT IN.
LET IT FIRM UP,
HARDEN UP A LITTLE BIT.
LOOK AT THAT. KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE ONE OF THEM BLOOMIN' CARP.
SLICE OF RYE BREAD.
SO IT'S JUST LIKE
FRIED CHICKEN, BUT NOT.
JUST LIKE LOBSTER,
BUT NOT.
I REALLY DO HAVE
TO ASK YOU...
ANY RESEMBLANCE?
DO IT TO IT.
OH!
MAN, WHEN HE SAID
SOAK IT IN SOME HOT SAUCE...
MMM.
GREAT. IT FRIES WELL.
IT'S NICE AND MOIST.
I GOTTA SAY THAT THE BATTER
AND THE SCORING METHOD
MAKES IT WORK.
I HAVEN'T TASTED ANY BONES.
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
FRIED CARP DINNER.
THAT'S KILLER.
ONCE YOU GET THE FIRST BITE,
YOU KNOW, IT SURPRISES YOU.
IT FALLS APART,
AND IT'S REALLY TENDER.
EXCELLENT.
FLAKY.
IT'S NOT FISHY AT ALL.
IT'S GREAT.
ALWAYS FRESH.
BUT NOT ALWAYS FRIED.
CARP CHOWDER. HOME-STYLE,
HOMEMADE, HOMESPUN.
MMM. THAT IS REALLY GREAT.
VERY SAVORY.
THAT'S LEGIT.
THEY'RE EVEN PICKLING IT.
LIKE PICKLED HERRING?
YES.
VINEGAR, PICKLING SPICE...
AND ONIONS.
OKAY.
OKAY, YOU GONNA HELP ME
CARRY THIS IN?
YEAH. WHAT DO YOU DO
WHEN I'M NOT HERE?
ARE YOU LIFTING?
I'M INTO HERE!
WHOA!
IN THE COOLER.
THAT'S A FRESH BUCKET.
THAT'S THE FINISHED
PRODUCT.
THAT'S NOT GONNA WORK,
IS IT?
NO. YOU HAVE TO GET
A BIGGER PIECE.
I WANT TO REALLY JUST GET
THE FLAVOR, THE ESSENCE.
MMM.
NICE PICKLING.
THIS HAS SOME NICE
TEXTURE TO IT.
UM, I'M DRIVING.
IT'S COLD IN HERE.
YES, IT IS.
CAN I GO?
YES.
THANK YOU.
IT'S SWEET. IT'S TASTY.
THIS IS
PRIMO PICKLED CARP.
TASTES LIKE PICKLE
WITH A SUSHI FEEL.
YOU THINK?
BUT, HEY, PICKED,
CHOWDERED OR FRIED,
THIS JOINT'S CRANKING OUT
A TON OF CARP A WEEK.
THANK YOU.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
IT'S JUST DIFFERENT.
YOU CAN'T GET IT DONE
THE WAY THEY DO IT HERE.
I LIKE CARP,
BUT CATFISH IS MY FAVORITE.
CATFISH DINNER?
YEAH, THEY'RE FRYING
THOSE, TOO.
(man) THAT'S A WHOLE
CATFISH RIGHT THERE.
I ALWAYS GET
THE MEDIUM CATFISH.
WE HAVE A MEDIUM SIZE
AND A LARGE SIZE.
ONE WILL FILL YOU UP.
THAT'S A BIT OVER A POUND.
FOR ONE PERSON.
SALT AND PEPPER.
WE USE THE BREADING
FOR CARP AND CATFISH.
NOW DO YOU TICKLE
THIS FISH, TOO?
NO, WE JUST WANT
TO GET THE FLOUR
IN THOSE THREE SCORE MARKS
SO THE FISH FRIES UP EVENLY.
AND THAT'S IT.
SO THIS WILL GET
FRIED UP.
THAT TAKES 15 MINUTES.
IS SHE READY?
IT'S READY.
(whistles)
I LIKE TO HOLD IT
UPSIDE DOWN A WHILE,
LET ALL THE GREASE
DRAIN OUT OF IT.
I EVEN LIKE
TO STAND 'EM UP.
WHAT A DISH
OF CATFISH.
LOOK AT THAT.
I LIKE IT.
FLAKY AND TENDER.
IT DOESN'T TASTE OILY. ANYTIME
YOU CAN HAVE FISH ON THE BONE--
GET ALL THAT FLAVOR.
THAT'S A NICE PIECE OF FISH.
TASTES LIKE IT'S
STRAIGHT OUT THE WATER.
TENDER.
OH, IT'S AWESOME.
IT IS VERY DELICIOUS.
I WENT AND GOT
A MEDIUM TODAY.
SHOULD HAVE GOTTEN
A LARGE.
HI, BUDDY.
IT'S A NEIGHBORHOOD PLACE.
BIG NEIGHBORHOOD PLACE.
YEAH, IT IS.
YOU CAN'T BEAT
AN ORIGINAL.
THIS IS THE WAY TO FISH.
WE'RE GOING FISHING,
'CAUSE WE GO TO JOE TESS.
YEAH.
WE'RE GOING FISHING.
LET ME SEE IF I CAN PULL OUT
A 2-POUNDER OFF THE MENU.
WE DON'T GOTTA CLEAN IT.
WE DON'T GOTTA SIT IN THE SUN.
QUITE THE SPORTSMAN,
YOU ARE.
YEAH.
NEXT STOP, PITTSBURGH...
SPAGHETTI WITH MEATBALLS
AND MARINARA.
IT'S HOW I LIKE IT.
GOOD, FULL FLAVOR.
FOR ITALIAN CLASSICS...
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SINCE 1977.
MMM. OH, THAT'S GOOD.
IF YOU'RE FROM PITTSBURGH,
YOU PROBABLY KNOW ABOUT
THE NEIGHBORHOOD
CALLED "THE RUN,"
AND YOU GOTTA BE
FROM PITTSBURGH
IF YOU KNOW ABOUT THIS PLACE--
BIG JIM'S IN THE RUN.
NOW IT'S NOTHING FANCY
ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT INSIDE, THEY'RE COOKING UP
OLD-SCHOOL ITALIAN,
AND THE LOCALS SAY
IT'S BETTER THAN EVER.
SPAGHETTI WITH MEATBALLS
AND MARINARA.
I CAN TELL
THEY'RE HOMEMADE.
HALF A CHICKEN PARM.
WHOLE PARM.
GOOD, HUH?
GOOD.
MMM, IT'S GOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FROM BAKED ZITI
AND HOMEMADE LASAGNA...
MMM.
TO HAND-STUFFED SHELLS...
THIS IS AMAZING.
AND A VEAL PARM THAT'S
AS BIG AS YOUR HEAD...
LOOK AT THIS THING.
I'M GONNA BE HERE A WHILE.
ALL MADE BIG JIM'S WAY.
IN 1977, MY UNCLE
BOUGHT THE BUILDING
AND TURNED IT
INTO BIG JIM'S.
JIM'S NEPHEW
VITO BOCHICCHIO...
HOW ARE YOU FOLKS
DOING TONIGHT?
BOUGHT THE JOINT IN '92
WITH A COUPLE OF PARTNERS...
IS THERE ANYTHING ELSE
WITH THIS RIG?
TO KEEP THE BIG JIM'S
TRADITION ALIVE.
THE RECIPES--MOST OF THEM
WERE THE SAME ONES
THAT MY GRANDMOTHER HAD THAT
SHE BROUGHT OVER FROM ITALY.
HANDED DOWN FROM
WHEN JIM HAD IT.
YEAH.
CAN I GET A SHOT
OF MARINARA?
YEAH.
LIKE THE ONE-OF-A-KIND
RED SAUCE...
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
PARTNER GARY BURDICK IS
CRANKING OUT THE BIG JIM'S WAY.
WE ARE GONNA PURéE
SOME FRESH GREEN PEPPER,
CELERY, CARROTS
AND ONIONS.
WE'RE GONNA PURéE THEM?
IN THE OLIVE OIL.
OKAY.
THIS WILL NOW OFFICIALLY BE ONE
OF THE MOST INTERESTING WAYS
I'VE EVER SEEN
TOMATO SAUCE MADE.
(imitates record
scratching)
WHEN YOU COOK IT THIS WAY,
IT HAS SOME TEXTURE.
THAT'S ACTUALLY THE BEGINNING
OF SOME MARINARA SAUCE.
OREGANO, BASIL, GARLIC...
OREGANO, BASIL, GARLIC,
SALT, PEPPER, AND WE'RE
GONNA LET IT SAUTé
JUST FOR FIVE MINUTES,
NO MORE.
WE NEED TOMATO SAUCE.
THAT'S WHY YOU WEAR
THAT COLOR.
YEAH. NOW YOU KNOW WHY.
I'LL BE OVER HERE.
NOW HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA LET THIS COOK FOR?
FIVE TO SIX HOURS.
SO IS THIS READY?
YEAH.
LOOK.
IT'S REDUCED DOWN NICELY.
THOSE ARE THE CHUNKS
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
LET ME TRY
A LITTLE TASTE.
OKAY.
MMM. NICE BOUQUET.
HMM, '76. NO, '77.
MMM. IT'S VERY LIGHT
AND VERY FRESH.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW WHAT I REALLY GET?
SOME OF THE SWEETNESS
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
DELICIOUS, MAN. REALLY NICE.
THE SAUCE IS REALLY RICH,
AND THE MEATBALLS
TASTE AUTHENTIC.
TWO SPAGHETTI SPECIALS
WITH MEATBALLS.
IS THIS THE SAME RECIPE
THAT JIM WAS DOING?
I BELIEVE SO.
I THINK I'VE TWEAKED
THIS A BIT, THOUGH.
HMM.
13 EGGS.
NOT 12, NOT 14...
NOW WE HAVE OREGANO,
BASIL--A LOT OF BASIL--
SALT, PEPPER,
PECORINO ROMANO.
REALLY?
THAT'S A NICE SHARP
LITTLE TASTE THERE.
GRANULATED GARLIC, PANKO.
PANKO.
JAPANESE BREADCRUMBS.
I USE IT 'CAUSE IT DOESN'T
HAVE A FLAVOR TO IT.
THE FLAVOR COMES
OUT OF THE MEAT.
SO THAT JUST GETS MIXED?
WE MIX. THIS WILL GIVE ME
ABOUT 65 TO 70 MEATBALLS,
4 OUNCES EACH.
WOW.
NOW WE GOTTA START ROLLING,
AND NOT TOO TIGHT.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
MEATBALL.
PUTTING THEM NIGHT-NIGHT.
DON'T WANT 'EM TO DRY OUT.
350 DEGREES,
ABOUT 35, 40 MINUTES?
YEAH.
MMM.
CHECK 'EM OUT.
THEY LOOK GOOD TO ME.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
AWFUL HOT.
I'M LIKE THE EVIL KNIEVEL
OF HOT FOOD JUMPING.
MMM. THAT'S A MONEY
MEATBALL, MAN. LOOK AT THAT.
GREAT TEXTURE. NOT OVERCOOKED.
MADE THE RIGHT WAY.
NICE JOB WITH
THE PANKO, TOO.
GOOD. THANK YOU.
IT'S HOW I LIKE IT.
GOOD, FULL FLAVOR.
THERE'S NOT A BAD THING
ON THE MENU.
AND THIS IS ONE
OF THOSE JOINTS
WHERE THE CROWD
KNOWS THE MENU...
THANK YOU.
INSIDE AND OUT.
I EAT HERE AT LEAST
FOUR DAYS A WEEK.
EVERY FRIDAY EVENING.
I LIKE THE PIZZA A LOT.
DEFINITELY THE PIZZA.
THAT DUDE THROWING
SOME SKINS BACK THERE--
YOU SHOULD SEE HIM.
I FELT LIKE I WAS IN ITALY.
GONNA NEED A LASAGNA.
IT'S GOOD.
GNOCCHI--VERY LIGHT
AND FRESH AND GOOD.
AND ONE OF THE BIGGEST
HITTERS HERE--
THE VEAL PARMESAN
SANDWICH.
DUDE, HOW MUCH DO YOU THINK
YOU CAN PUT DOWN?
PROBABLY HALF OF THIS.
REALLY?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BREADED VEAL.
A LITTLE EGG WASH.
VERY SIMPLE.
WE WANT THE FLAVOR TO COME
OUT OF THE SAUCE. THAT'S GOOD.
NOW WE GET SOME VEAL.
WE PUT TWO PIECES OF THIS.
TWO PIECES OF THAT?
YEAH.
THAT PUTS THE SHAMA LAMA
IN THE DING DONG.
NO SEASONING IN THE FLOUR?
NOPE.
THE FLOUR STICKS TO THE MEAT,
EGG WASH STICKS TO THE FLOUR,
AND THEN THE PANKO
STICKS TO THE EGG WASH.
YOU'RE SO FLY WHEN YOU FRY.
THESE ARE GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
THREE, FOUR MINUTES.
GOTTA FIND A BUN FOR THAT.
OH, WHERE'D YOU GET THAT,
PAUL BUNYAN BAKERY?
DOWN...
MARINARA.
DOESN'T THAT LOOK GOOD?
A LITTLE PROVOLONE.
A COUPLE
NICE BIG SLABS.
YEP.
AND THEN THAT'S GONNA
GO DOWNTOWN IN THE OVEN.
YEAH.
HOW WE LOOKIN'?
OH, CHEESE IS MELTING.
STAND BY. I'M GONNA GIVE YOU
A FULL REPORT IN JUST A MINUTE.
(giggling)
WHEN YOU LOOK IN THE DICTIONARY
UNDER "RIDICULOUS,"
THAT SANDWICH
IS RIGHT THERE.
ANY RESEMBLANCE?
MMM.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
THE VEAL IS AS TENDER
AS I'VE HAD.
MMM.
I MEAN, EVERY PART OF IT,
FROM THE MELTED PROVOLONE
TO THE CRUSTY BREAD--
THE ITALIAN BREAD...
IN A BRICK BUILDING JOINT ACROSS
FROM A LITTLE OLD BALL PARK
AND A WAR MEMORIAL...
YEAH, IT'S EXACTLY WHAT
I EXPECTED TO FIND.
ONE MORE BITE,
AND THEN I'LL GO.
I EAT AS MUCH AS I CAN,
AND THEN I TAKE THE REST HOME,
AND I EAT LUNCH AND DINNER
FOR LIKE THREE DAYS.
JUST COULDN'T FINISH
ALL THE BREAD.
I ACTUALLY DON'T FEEL TOO BAD.
A LITTLE TIRED,
BUT OTHER THAN THAT, JUST GONNA
HANG OUT FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
MY FEET UP.
YOU MENTION
BIG JIM'S IN THE RUN,
AND PEOPLE KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S VERY GOOD
FOR ITALIAN, FOR SANDWICHES,
FOR THE SOUP.
IT'S HARD TO FIND GOOD
WEDDING SOUP IN RESTAURANTS...
BUT NOT AT BIG JIM'S.
ONE OF THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
MMM. MMM.
THIS IS SO MACK.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
BIG JIM'S IN
PITTSBURGH, PENNSYLVANIA...
SPAGHETTI
WITH MEAT SAUCE.
IS DOING IT ALL,
OLD SCHOOL.
THANK YOU.
GOOD, HEARTY FOOD.
THE SAME WAY
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
ALWAYS CONSISTENT,
AND IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
GOOD, DOWN-HOME,
WHOLESOME FOOD.
JUST LIKE THIS CLASSIC.
ITALIAN WEDDING SOUP.
PROBABLY THE BIGGEST
SELLER WE HAVE HERE.
REALLY?
YOU EAT THIS OFTEN--
ITALIAN WEDDING SOUP?
YEAH, I'M ITALIAN.
MINESTRA MARITATA,
WHICH JUST MEANS BLENDED
FLAVORS OR MARRIED FLAVORS.
WE KIND OF MAKE OUR STOCK
AT THE SAME TIME AS WE COOK.
WE HAVE LOTS OF CELERY,
CARROTS, ONIONS.
HOW OFTEN DO YOU GUYS
MAKE THIS?
A POT EVERY DAY.
EVERY SINGLE DAY YOU
MAKE A NEW ONE?
YEAH.
REALLY?
YEAH, EVERY DAY.
NOW I NEED SOME CHICKENS.
AND SO THESE GUYS ARE
JUST GONNA GO DOWNTOWN?
WE'RE GONNA GO DOWN.
BIGGEST BIRDS AS YOU CAN FIND.
ALL RIGHT, THEY'RE HAPPY.
LET'S GET SALT AND PEPPER.
A COUPLE OUNCES. WE'RE GONNA LET
IT COOK FOR AT LEAST AN HOUR.
NOW ARE YOU GONNA
TAKE THOSE BIRDS OUT
BEFORE THEY START
TO FALL APART...
YEAH, THAT'S THE KEY.
THEN TAKE THE MEAT OFF?
YOU GOTTA GET IT
RIGHT IN TIME.
PULL IT CLEAN.
THE OTHER MARRIAGE
TO THE MEAT IS THE ESCAROLE.
SOME PEOPLE PUT SPINACH
IN THEIR WEDDING SOUP,
BUT WE USE ESCAROLE.
NICE BROACH.
OH, THAT'S A MOUND
OF MEATBALLS.
LOOK AT THAT. YOU HAVE NOT HAD
ONE OF THEM COME OFF THE TRAY.
NICE AND SIMPLE FOR THIS
ITALIAN WEDDING. I LIKE THAT.
SO GIVE THAT AN HOUR,
AND WE'LL ADD THE CHICKEN.
SO WE GOT DARK MEAT
AND WHITE MEAT?
YEAH, EVERYTHING.
THAT SMELLS GOOD. SO AS SOON
AS THIS GOES IN, WE'RE READY?
WE'RE ABOUT READY, YEP.
LET'S SERVE SOME UP.
I WANT TO TRY IT.
YOU WANT TO TRY?
MMM. OH.
THAT IS REALLY TASTY.
THIS IS SO MACK.
SEE? I'VE GOT THE HUNCH
ALMOST, WORKING ON THIS.
THE GREENS ARE AWESOME.
I'M TAKING A CULINARY STROLL
WITH THE ESCAROLE.
WE HAVE BIGGER SPOONS.
LISTEN--
I'M SO CLOSE TO JUST PUTTING
THE WHOLE THING IN MY MOUTH.
DO YOU TASTE THE MARRIAGE
OF THE MEAT...
OH.
AND THE GREENS?
I FEEL LIKE I'M AT
THE RECEPTION RIGHT NOW.
SUCH THE NAME.
I LOVE IT. IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITE SOUPS.
PLEASE DON'T TELL
MY HUSBAND'S AUNT
BECAUSE SHE MAKES
AWESOME WEDDING SOUP,
AND SHE WON'T LIKE HEARING
THAT I WAS CHEATING ON HER.
GARLIC TOAST
FOR EVERYBODY.
RESTAURANTS LIKE THIS THAT HAVE
BEEN AROUND A LONG TIME
ALWAYS MAKE IT
THE WAY WE LIKE IT.
QUALITY'S THERE, QUANTITY'S
THERE. WHAT'S NOT TO LIKE?
I WANT 'EM TO SAY WHAT
MY UNCLE WOULD HAVE SAID--
(speaking indistinctly
in Italian)
WHICH MEANS, "WHEN YOU
COME HERE, YOU EAT WELL."
WHEN YOU START EATING SOME REAL
GOOD FOOD, YOU END UP GETTING
THAT--WHAT I LIKE TO CALL--
FOOD COMA.
I'M SORRY. MY FAULT.
WELL, LET ME JUST PUT SOME
GLASSES ON THIS CAT
AND SPIKE HIS HAIR UP,
AND YOU GOT A NEW HOST.
WELL, THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED FOR
SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."