HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
STRAWBERRY HOTCAKES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE THIS.
WHAT'S FOR BREAKFAST...
GRANOLA, FRUIT AND YOGURT.
MM-MMM.
IN NEW MEXICO...
GET THAT OMELET.
A SOUTHWEST ROADHOUSE...
GREAT COMFORT FOOD.
DOIN' ALL KINDS OF COOKIN'...
MOTULENOS.
SCRAPPLE UP.
FOR ALL SORTS OF FOLKS...
HAVE YOU EVER HAD
THE SCRAPPLE?
NO.
EVEN OSCAR WINNER GENE HACKMAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT SCRAPPLE IS.
YEAH--I DO.
EVERYTHING BUT THE OINKS.
MMM.
IN NEW ORLEANS...
CORN BEEF HASH?
WHERE A BIG EASY BREAKFAST...
MMM. IT'S WONDERFUL.
MEANS BANANAS FOSTER
FRENCH TOAST...
IT'S LIKE HAVING
DESSERT FOR BREAKFAST.
OR A HOMEMADE BAGEL...
IT'S WONDERFUL.
BOILED UP FROM SCRATCH.
FRESH LOX
AND KILLER BAGELS.
AND IN PITTSBURGH...
A RASPBERRY FRENCH
AND A FULL PUMPKIN.
A FAMILY JOINT DOING
ALL KINDS OF PANCAKES...
OATMEAL PANCAKES,
BANANA PANCAKES.
AND FAMILY FAVORITES...
AWESOME-TASTING.
JUST ASK MY FAMILY.
THIS IS WHAT YOUR GREAT UNCLE
USED TO MAKE.
WHOO-WOO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
THE SHOW'S CALLED
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
BUT WE GOT ROOM FOR
ALL KIND OF FUNKY JOINTS,
LIKE A ROADHOUSE.
NOW THE LAST ROADHOUSE
WE WERE AT
WAS AT PATRICK'S ROADHOUSE,
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA,
PACIFIC COAST HIGHWAY.
TODAY, WELL, WE'RE IN
SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO,
ON THE I-25
AT HARRY'S ROADHOUSE,
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING UP
ALL KINDS OF BREAKFAST,
AND, BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
HOMEMADE SCRAPPLE.
(man) SCRAPPLE UP.
I WAS IN PHILLY.
THEY HAD SCRAPPLE.
AND NO ONE
COULD TELL ME
EXACTLY WHAT PART OF THE PIG
IT CAME FROM.
EVERYTHING BUT THE OINKS.
SCRAPPLE UP.
IT'S A BREAKFAST STAPLE BACK
IN PHILLY...
OKAY.
WHERE HARRY SHAPIRO GREW UP...
YOU GOT THAT OMELET?
HANGING OUT AT SOME CLASSIC
EAST COAST DINERS.
LET'S GET THIS OUT.
A PLACE THAT SERVES GOOD FOOD
AT A REASONABLE PRICE
WHERE YOU CAN HANG OUT.
AND THAT'S WHAT
HE'S DOING HERE.
HI, GUYS.
THE WAFFLES, THE PANCAKES.
IT'S THE DINER.
IT'S THE COMFORT THING.
BUT IT'S GOT
THE SOUTHWEST THING GOING ON.
MOTULENOS.
THE BREAKFAST BURRITO
OR THE HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
IT'S CRAZY.
I'M THIS JEWISH KID
IN PHILADELPHIA,
AND I FALL IN LOVE
WITH MEXICAN FOOD.
I SAY, THAT'S IT.
I'M MOVING TO SANTA FE.
WHOO.
AND WITH HIS WIFE PEYTON...
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT
DOWN HERE?
BUYING AN OLD GAS STATION
TURNED RESTAURANT
ON ROUTE 66...
HOW'S LUNCH?
RUNNING AN ALL-DAY ROADHOUSE...
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD, AND IT'S
ALWAYS A PLEASANT PLACE TO BE.
HI, GUYS.
FOR ALL SORTS OF FOLKS
FROM ALL AROUND SANTA FE...
KIND OF A STAPLE.
EVEN OSCAR-WINNING ACTOR
GENE HACKMAN...
AND NOBODY PAYS ANY ATTENTION,
YOU KNOW?
JUST KIND OF CRUISE IN--
YEAH.
UNTIL WE COME DRAGGING OUR
CAMERAS ACROSS YOUR TABLE.
THE STAFF AND THE OWNERS
ARE SO FRIENDLY.
EVERYTHING THEY MAKE
IS JUST TASTY AND YUMMY.
EVERYTHING IS TASTY
AND YUMMY.
EVERYTHING FROM
TRADITIONAL MEXICAN
AND NATIVE NEW MEXICAN FOODS
TO VERY ECLECTIC REGIONAL
AMERICAN SPECIALTIES.
REGIONAL? ECLECTIC? YA THINK?
PENNSYLVANIA DUTCH
SCRAPPLE
HAS A LOT PORK LIVER
IN IT.
PORK LIVER. MMM.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD
THE SCRAPPLE?
NO.
YOU KNOW WHAT SCRAPPLE IS.
YEAH--I DO.
IT'S USUALLY
PORK SCRAPS AND CORNMEAL,
BUT HARRY'S DOIN' IT DIFFERENT.
WE'RE MAKING YOUR SCRAPPLE
OUT OF PORK BUTT?
WE ARE.
OKAY, I'M A LITTLE BIT MORE
AT EASE.
SO YOU'RE CHOPPING THAT UP
INTO ABOUT A 2-INCH CUBE.
THIS IS PORK STOCK WITH VEGGIES,
ONIONS AND THE WHOLE GIDDYAP?
YEP.
THIS IN THAR.
SET THE TEMP FOR SIMMER,
30 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GRIND IT.
I GET TO BE PART
OF THE SCRAPPLE NATION.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
(whistles)
THIS IS THE CULINARY CHAPEL
OF THE SCRAPPLE.
WE'RE HALFWAY THROUGH
THE SCRAPPLE ADVENTURE...
YEAH.
AND YOU'RE DANCING?
THIS IS THAT SAME STOCK
THAT WE COOKED THE PORK BUTT
IN THE FIRST TIME.
PUTTING IN POLENTA,
SOME PEPPER, SOME THYME,
MARJORAM.
SAGE.
SALT--THROW IT IN.
LOOKING GOOD.
I CAN FEEL IT THICKENING UP
BIG TIME RIGHT NOW.
THE MORE YOU COOK IT,
THE BETTER IT GETS.
YEAH.
PUT IT IN THE PANS,
FREEZE IT.
AND WE TAKE IT OUT
AS WE NEED IT.
SLICE OFF A SLAB,
A CHUNK-A.
LITTLE FLOUR,
SHAKE OFF THE EXCESS.
LITTLE CLARIFIED BUTTER.
WHOA. HOW IS MY SCRAPPLE?
CAN I GET
A LITTLE DRUMROLL?
(drums on table)
THAT'S GOOD.
SERIOUSLY, THAT'S GREAT.
GOOD.
AND THE CRUNCH--
AWESOME, MAN.
AND I DIDN'T WANT
TO LIKE IT.
SERIOUSLY, YOU'RE GONNA LIKE
THIS. YOU GOT TO TRY IT.
THERE YOU GO,
'CAUSE THIS IS HABANERO.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YOU KNOW, GUY, THE--
IT WAS HOT.
THIS SCRAPPLE IS
THE ONLY SCRAPPLE I'LL EAT.
IT'S KIND OF A COMBINATION
OF SAUSAGE AND HUSH PUPPY.
MMM. IT'S FABULOUS.
DELICIOUS.
MM-HMM.
IT IS REALLY GOOD.
(woman) BUT THEY ALSO HAVE
THE PANCAKES, THE FRENCH TOAST.
I LOVE DINER FOOD.
(woman) ALL THE KINDS OF THINGS
YOU WOULD EXPECT
WITH A SPECIAL TWIST.
LIKE LEMON-RICOTTA PANCAKES
WITH STRAWBERRIES,
MASSIVE HOMEMADE
CINNAMON ROLLS...
MMM-MM.
AND BLUE CORN WAFFLES
DONE HARRY'S WAY...
IT HAS STRIPS OF BACON
INSIDE THE WAFFLE ITSELF.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
MMM.
THE SUGAR WITH THE SALTY--
REALLY NICE AND TENDER.
BREAKFAST IS AWESOME OVER HERE,
AS ARE ALL THE MEALS.
IT'S JUST SOME GREAT COMFORT
FOOD AND GREAT TASTE,
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
CHILAQUILES.
AND ALL KINDS OF MEXICAN
AND SOUTHWESTERN FAVORITES...
MOTULENOS OVER EASY.
LIKE AN EGG,
BEAN AND TORTILLA DISH
WITH SALSA HARRY'S
MAKING HIMSELF.
(Harry) PEPPERCORNS, PANELA.
THIS IS THE REAL--
REAL CINNAMON.
CUMIN, ANISE.
TOAST THESE, REALLY KIND OF
OPEN UP THE FLAVOR ON 'EM.
SO WE'RE GONNA
GRIND THESE NOW.
WOW, TAKE A SMELL OF THAT.
WE ROASTED SOME
TOMATOES AND ONIONS,
GRILLED SOME GARLIC
ON THE FLATTOP.
SO TOMATOES.
ROASTED ONIONS
AND GARLIC,
ORANGE JUICE,
LIME JUICE.
THAT'S A BLENDER.
LITTLE VEGGIE STOCK,
LITTLE SALT.
POUR THIS IN.
I CUT THE HABANERO.
I'M GONNA STICK
A TOOTHPICK THROUGH IT.
AND WASH YOUR HANDS.
DON'T RUB YOUR EYE
RIGHT NOW.
THAT JUST SITS THERE.
AND THEN THE SPICE MIX.
BUT THE TASTE, BECAUSE
WE DIDN'T BLEND THE HABANERO IN,
NEEDS TO SIT THERE
OVERNIGHT.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
THAT'S GONNA GO ON TOP OF WHAT?
THE MOTULENOS.
FRY THE TORTILLAS.
SO YOU JUST PUT
A LITTLE CRISP ON THESE,
BUT NOT MAKING
A TORTILLA CHIP.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF REFRIED BEANS.
YOU CAN GET THE EGGS
ANYWAY YOU WANT.
PUT A LITTLE SALSA ON.
EGG GOES ON TOP.
A LITTLE MORE SALSA,
SOME HAM.
SOME PEAS
AND THEN THIS
IS QUESO FRESCO.
OH, WHICH I LOVE.
FRIED PLANTAINS.
AND THIS IS ALL
FROM THE YUCATáN.
FANTASTIC.
GOOD.
THAT'S A NICE BREAKFAST DISH
RIGHT THERE.
LITTLE SWEETNESS
FROM THE LITTLE PLANTAIN.
KILLER SALSA.
DO I GET TO GO
TO THE NEXT ROUND?
IT'S REAL SATISFYING,
'CAUSE IT'S A LITTLE PICANTE,
A LITTLE BIT SPICY.
MAN, IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
IT'S JUST A GREAT
SANTA FE INSTITUTION.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
IT'S A PART OF SANTA FE.
IT'S AMAZING.
EVERY DAY YOU GOT
TO PROVE YOURSELF.
PANCAKES--ONE CAKE.
THAT'S WHY YOU STAY
A GREAT RESTAURATEUR.
THAT CAN GO.
WHAT MAKES THE ROADHOUSE
ONE OF YOUR GO-TO SPOTS?
YOU KNOW, I CAN COME
ANYWAY I WANT TO.
YOU MEAN COMPARED TO--
YOU LOOK PRETTY GOOD.
I'M--
EXCEPT YOUR HAIR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOUR HAIR?
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO NEW ORLEANS...
MMM.
THAT IS GREAT ANDOUILLE.
WHERE A TASTE OF LOUISIANA
INCLUDES, WHAT ELSE,
HOMEMADE BAGELS AND LOX...
I'M A BAGEL FANATIC.
AND A SHOT OF WHEATGRASS.
SHOCKING AT FIRST.
HERE ON TRIPLE "D,"
ONE OF THE THINGS YOU GOT
TO KNOW
IS TO EXPECT THE UNEXPECTED.
NOW HERE I AM IN NEW ORLEANS,
SO YOU'RE EXPECTING
BOURBON STREET,
JAMBALAYA AND BEIGNETS,
BUT, NO, NO, NO,
TODAY YOU GET A NEIGHBORHOOD
AND A JUICE BAR THAT MAKES
HOMEMADE BAGELS AND LOX.
THE BAGEL PLATE
WITH FRESH LOX.
MMM.
TELL ME THAT'S NOT
A HOMEMADE-LOOKING BAGEL.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
BOILED AND BAKED LIKE THEY DO
IN NEW YORK.
PLUS THE LOX ARE NICE AND SALTY.
YOU'RE IN NEW ORLEANS, RIGHT?
YOU'RE IN THE MELTING POT.
SO THIS IS THE MELTING POT
OF THE MELTING POT.
'CAUSE HERE AT SURREY,
IT'S ALL ABOUT OWNER
GREG SURREY'S FAVORITES.
I PLAYED MUSIC AND COOKED
WHEN I DIDN'T HAVE A GIG
JUST SO I COULD EAT,
AND I GOT GOOD AT IT.
IT'S ECLECTIC.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT'S GOT SO MANY DIFFERENT
APPEALS TO IT.
I FEEL LIKE
I'M IN CALIFORNIA.
GRANOLA, FRUIT AND YOGURT.
YOU GET SOME REAL NICE CAJUN
INFLUENCES FROM THE ANDOUILLE.
CORN BEEF HASH?
CORN BEEF HASH WITH ANDOUILLE
AND BOUDIN SAUSAGE.
BANANAS FOSTER
FRENCH TOAST--
IT'S ALMOST LIKE HAVING
DESSERT FOR BREAKFAST.
MMM. IT'S WONDERFUL.
WE TRIED TO, LIKE, COVER
ALL THE BASES IN BREAKFAST.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA
HAND-MAKE EVERYTHING?
YEAH.
WHICH BRINGS US BACK
TO THE BAGELS.
ON TRIPLE "D," WE'VE BEEN
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
BUT NOBODY HAS MADE
THEIR OWN.
IT'S A WHOLE DIFFERENT ANIMAL
WHEN THEY'RE FRESH LIKE THAT.
OH, LORD, THIS IS SO GOOD.
I'M A BAGEL FANATIC...
REALLY?
AND I'VE NEVER MADE A BAGEL.
BUT CHEF PAUL ARTIGUES
HAS CRANKED THEM OUT
BY THE THOUSANDS.
I START OUT
WITH LUKEWARM WATER.
AND THEN WE DO THE YEAST.
AND THAT'S THAT
FAST-ACTING YEAST.
YEAH, IT TAKES ABOUT
A MINUTE OR SO.
YOU REALLY KNOW IT'S READY
WHEN YOU CAN SMELL IT.
PERFUMES UP A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, LIKE YOU POURED
A BEER IN THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR
AT A TIME.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SALT AND SUGAR.
I'M GONNA ADD
THE SUGAR FIRST.
I LET THAT MIX UP A LITTLE BIT,
THEN I GO FOR THE SALT.
I HIT IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF HONEY. SO THAT'S READY.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT RISE ONCE.
THEN I'LL PUNCH IT DOWN.
RISES A SECOND TIME.
SO LIKE WE'RE MAKING
PIZZA DOUGH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START BUSTIN'
'EM OUT INTO THE--
YEAH.
KIND OF GOT A GOOD EYE FOR
EXACTLY WHAT 4 OUNCES IS
AT THIS POINT, SO--
NOT YOUR FIRST RODEO.
YOU ROLL IT INTO ITSELF,
OKAY.
AND JUST STICK YOUR FINGER
UP THROUGH THE MIDDLE.
MAKE A HOLE.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
OOH-HA-HA.
HOW AM I DOING?
DOIN' PRETTY GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING TOMORROW?
WE'RE GONNA NEED MORE BAGELS.
I'M DOUBLE-PARKED.
OH, HO.
THAT'S HOW IT IS, HUH?
WE'RE GONNA LET 'EM RISE
FOR A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA BOIL 'EM.
I'M GONNA PUT SOME HONEY
IN THERE, 3 OR 4 TABLESPOONS...
OKAY.
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
MAKE THE HOLE A LITTLE BIGGER
AND JUST DROP 'EM IN.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO THEY'RE ABOUT READY
TO GET FLIPPED.
HIT 'EM ON THE SIDE
AND OVER THEY GO.
I'M GETTING, LIKE,
A LITTLE BAGEL FACIAL.
YEAH, LET 'EM COOL DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
OF EGG WASH,
AND THEN JUST STICK IT RIGHT
ON TOP OF THE POPPY.
IT'S FLOPPY IN THE POPPY.
REALLY?
SEE, I'M GONNA SPRINKLE.
I MEAN, THAT'S KIND OF
WEST COAST.
YOU KNOW,
I'M JUST SAYIN'.
JUST... (whistles)
YEP, JUST ALL OVER.
WE DON'T HAVE TO REALLY WORRY
ABOUT STICKING, RIGHT?
NO, THAT'S WHAT
THE OATS ARE FOR.
NOW IN THE OVEN, 350.
20 MINUTES, HALF AN HOUR,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
YEAH, 220, 221,
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
THESE BAD BOYS ARE DONE?
YEP.
MMM!
SO THEY'RE ALL UNIQUE. EVERY ONE
LOOKS A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
I THINK THAT'S THE ONE I LIKE.
SMELL'S KILLER.
THERE YOU GO.
WOW. IT'S HOT.
MMM.
AND THAT RIGHT THERE
IS COMING RIGHT TO THE PLANT.
THAT'S IT.
TASTES FRESH.
IT'S MUCH MORE DOUGHY.
YOU CAN TELL THAT IT'S HOMEMADE.
AND YOU'RE ENJOYING
THE BAGELS AND LOX?
YES.
(man) LOX ARE GREAT.
NOW WE DO SOME SALMON.
TRIM IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
OTHERWISE IT'S NOT GONNA
CURE RIGHT.
CUT IT RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
EQUAL PARTS...
SALT AND SUGAR?
SALT AND SUGAR,
WHITE PEPPER AND BLACK PEPPER,
BOTH CRACKED.
YOU GET A BETTER
REAL PEPPER FLAVOR
COMING OUT OF THIS.
I'LL TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF THIS,
PUT IT DOWN FIRST.
SOME FRESH DILL.
I TRY TO GET IT
ON BOTH SIDES A LITTLE BIT.
I LIKE THE TUNE
OF THIS SONG.
STACK THE OTHER BAD BOY
ON TOP.
JUST MAKE A BIG SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU'RE REALLY LOADING HER UP.
WANT ME TO STRETCH THIS OUT,
SAME TEAM?
YEAH.
SEE? I HAVE A PURPOSE.
THEN I'LL WEIGHT THIS,
PRESS IT DOWN FOR ABOUT
TWO OR THREE DAYS.
AND THERE WE GO.
AND YOU SAID
YOU HAVE SOME DONE?
YEP.
YOU WANT ME TO GO GET IT?
OH, GOSH,
THAT'D BE A GREAT IDEA.
I'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
I DIDN'T THINK HE'D EVER ASK.
REALLY, BUT DON'T.
OH.
JUST KIND OF GET EVERYTHING YOU
WRAPPED IT UP IN OFF OF THERE.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH
READY TO GO.
WOW. FIRMS RIGHT UP,
DOESN'T IT?
MM-HMM.
KEEPING A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT PEPPER IN THERE'S NICE.
AND THIS IS HOW
THE PLATE-UP COMES.
GET A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM CHEESE
ON THERE, RED ONION,
COUPLE CAPERS.
THAT'S A BITE.
SHOULD CHANGE THE SIGN--
"WELCOME TO NEW ORLEANS--
FRESH LOX AND KILLER BAGELS."
GOOD. YOU KNOCKED THAT OUT
OF THE PARK, MY MAN.
THANK YOU, MAN.
RIDICULOUSLY GOOD.
THE TEXTURE'S PERFECT,
GOES WELL WITH THE CREAM CHEESE.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
I COULD SIT THERE
AND EAT THAT WHOLE THING.
YEAH.
WE LIKE TO GO TO PLACES
THAT HAVE DELICIOUS FOOD
THAT'S DIFFERENT.
ALL RIGHT, GET THIS--
HOMEMADE GRANOLA.
WOW, I GOT TO MAKE THIS
AT HOME.
HUNTER, WE'RE GONNA START
MAKING GRANOLA.
AND ABOUT A DOZEN
FRESH-SQUEEZED JUICES.
THE JUICE--THAT'S THE HIGHLIGHT.
I'LL TAKE AN APPLE GINGER
WITH A WHEATGRASS SHOOTER.
ALL RIGHT.
WOW, YOU CAN PICK UP
THE GINGER IN THAT.
MM-HMM.
TASTES NICE.
KEEPS YOU HEALTHY.
EVERY TIME I DO WHEATGRASS,
IT REMINDS ME
OF MOWING THE LAWN AS A KID.
IT'S NOT A SIPPING
KIND OF BEVERAGE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
IT'S GOOD. I MEAN, IT'S TASTY.
IT'S A LITTLE SHOCKING AT FIRST.
FRESH-SQUEEZED JUICE
IS AMAZING.
PARTY FOR MARCUS,
PARTY OF THREE.
THE JUICE BAR, YOU GOT
YOUR BAGELS AND LOX, RIGHT?
YOU GOT YOUR BOUDIN.
THAT'S RIGHT, BOUDIN,
A FAVORITE LOCAL SAUSAGE...
IT'S GOT A LITTLE SPICE TO IT.
AND, HERE, IT'S IN THE HASH.
NOW DO YOU MAKE
THE CORN BEEF HERE?
YEAH.
THEN I ADD BOUDIN,
AND THIS BOUDIN'S SMOKED BOUDIN.
AND ANDOUILLE,
A LITTLE BIT OF ROSEMARY.
POTATOES--PREROASTED,
NOTHING ON 'EM YET.
LITTLE CAJUN SEASONING,
MORE LIKE A SEASONING SALT.
THROW A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ROSEMARY DOWN.
ALMOST LIKE A GARNISH
THAT DOES SOMETHING.
(whistles)
WOW.
JUST LOOK AT THE RATIO.
MMM. SO THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ANDOUILLE,
LITTLE BIT OF THE CORN BEEF,
A LITTLE DIP. MMM.
THAT IS GREAT ANDOUILLE.
GOOD.
AND THEN THE BOUDIN BLANC,
IT ALMOST HAS A CREAMY TEXTURE.
YEAH.
WOW. THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S HASH-A-LICIOUS.
HASH-A-LICIOUS,
THERE YOU GO.
REALLY, DUDE,
TOP THREE BEST HASHES.
THANK YOU.
REALLY.
IT'S NICE AND CHUNKY.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE ABOUT IT.
PRETTY HAPPY?
I'M PRETTY ECSTATIC,
ACTUALLY.
IT'S AN AMAZING PLACE.
THE FOOD'S
ALWAYS WONDERFUL.
(man) AH, HERE WE GO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'M GONNA GET,
BUT I KNOW IT'S GONNA BE GREAT.
YOU THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA
BE STUCK TO SOME BEIGNETS
THE WHOLE TIME.
THERE WE GO.
I GOT TO TELL YOU, MAN,
PEOPLE LOVE THIS PLACE.
THAT'S WHAT I KEEP HEARING,
SO WE KEEP OPENING UP.
UP NEXT,
PANCAKES IN PITTSBURGH...
I GOT A PUMPKIN.
MMM.
AND A BREAKFAST SPECIALTY
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THAT'S A SPICY DISH.
MM-HMM.
UH-HUH.
I'M IN A PART
OF PITTSBURGH, PENNSYLVANIA,
KNOWN AS DORMONT.
IT'S ONE OF THOSE
REAL-DEAL NEIGHBORHOODS,
YOU KNOW, WHERE NOTHING
HAS CHANGED MUCH,
EVERYBODY KNOWS EACH OTHER
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
GREW UP HERE.
FOLKS IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD SAY
WHEN IT'S TIME FOR BREAKFAST,
YOU GOT TO CHECK OUT DOR-STOP.
I NEED A SHORT STACK
OF STRAWBERRY HOTCAKES.
I'VE GOT IT.
RIGHT HERE, BABE.
WHAT WAS THE FIRST CLAIM
TO FAME ON THE MENU?
THE PANCAKES.
EVERY TIME WE COME, THAT'S ALL
I EVER GET IS THE PANCAKES.
OATMEAL PANCAKES,
BANANA PANCAKES.
GOT A SHORT STACK
OF CHOCOLATE CHIP.
THEY'RE SO GOOD.
I ALWAYS GET
APPLE-CINNAMON PANCAKES.
APPLE CINNAMON.
THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
YOU CAN'T DUPLICATE THEM.
IS THIS, LIKE,
A SECRET RECIPE?
NO ONE KNOWS IT.
DO YOU LIKE THE PANCAKES?
YEAH!
ALL RIGHT.
AND VICKI LAWHORNE'S
BEEN MIXING IT UP HERE
FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS.
GLAD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
MY RECIPE ISN'T EXACT.
IT'S NOT EXACT?
YEAH, LIKE, I DON'T MEASURE.
I'M A DINER PERSON.
I COOK LIKE A DINER.
I ACT LIKE A DINER.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M DINER.
WE CALL IT HOTCAKES BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT DINERS CALLED IT.
SHORT STACK
OF STRAWBERRY HOTCAKES.
HOTCAKES.
GOT IT.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
OOH, I'M SORRY.
I'M A MESSY COOK.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU LOOK GOOD.
SUGAR.
OKAY.
VANILLA, EGGS, MILK
AND SALT.
NOW I HAVE TO MIX IT.
I'M GONNA STAND BACK
WHEN YOU START THAT,
'CAUSE I WASN'T DOING ANYTHING,
AND I GOT FLOUR ON ME.
I'M GONNA ADD THE REST
OF THE FLOUR.
AND MORE MILK.
MORE MILK.
THIS IS MARGARINE.
BAKING POWDER.
THAT IS THICK.
NOW YOU WAIT.
YOU'RE GONNA TASTE IT NOW.
YOU HAVE TO. I HAVE TO KNOW
IF IT NEEDS MORE SUGAR
OR MORE THIS OR MORE THAT.
NO, I'M PUTTING MORE MILK
IN THIS.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
YOU NEED TO TAKE THAT OFF.
MM-HMM.
I CAN'T LIFT IT.
WHO DOES IT NORMALLY?
MY DISH PERSON.
I DON'T KNOW.
MY--
THAT GUY.
ANY--IF THERE'S A MAN HERE,
I SAY, "COME ON."
WHAT ARE
YOU STANDING BACK FOR?
I'M AFRAID
YOU'RE GONNA SPILL IT.
STOP.
I DID STOP.
YOU GOT IT EVERYWHERE.
LOOK.
ALL I DID WAS HOLD IT.
YOU--
YOU WANT A TOWEL?
ALL I DID
WAS POUR THE BATTER.
FROM THE REGULAR BATTER,
WE DO THE OATMEAL CINNAMON,
BANANA CHOCOLATE CHIP,
WALNUT APPLE,
WHATEVER COMBINATION.
THIS IS WHERE
IT GOES DOWN?
THIS IS ONLY PANCAKES.
IT'S VICKI'S DAUGHTER LORI
WHO'S POURING AND FLIPPING.
APPLE-CINNAMON HOTCAKES
COMING OUT.
WE GOT A SET OF REGULAR,
OATMEAL HOTCAKES.
HOTCAKES.
I'M GONNA THROW
SOME BANANAS, WALNUTS.
YOU'RE READY.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
OH. IT'S MY FLIPPER.
IT'S A PUTTY KNIFE.
WELL, AFTER WORK I PAINT.
THEY'RE DONE.
LITTLE POWDER,
I DIDN'T GET IT ON YOU.
THAT'S THE REGULAR.
MMM. WOW.
THAT IS THE DENSEST PANCAKE
I'VE EVER HAD.
I MEAN, IT'S LIGHT.
IT'S FLUFFY.
BUT IT IS ABSOLUTELY
A HOTCAKE.
IT IS MORE LIKE CAKE
THAN IT IS LIKE A PANCAKE.
MM-HMM.
THEY'RE SWEET.
I DON'T USE BUTTER.
I DON'T USE SYRUP ON THEM
OR ANYTHING.
OKAY.
OATMEAL BANANA WALNUT.
MMM.
NICE CRUNCHY OUTSIDE.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
A HUGE WARM COOKIE
IS WHAT I'M EATING.
YOU KNOW WHAT? I COULDN'T HAVE
SAID IT BETTER MYSELF.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
BIG GIGANTIC MOIST
WARM COOKIE.
WHAT DO YOU NORMALLY HAVE?
PUMPKIN PANCAKES.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD
PUMPKIN PANCAKES ANYWHERE?
NO.
THESE ARE AWESOME.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO PUMPKIN.
WHAT ARE WE ADDING?
PUMPKIN,
CINNAMON AND SUGAR,
PUMPKIN SPICE,
SOME BAKING POWDER
AND A LITTLE MORE MILK.
WHAT?
THAT'S LIKE
LIQUID PUMPKIN PIE.
WOW, THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
LET'S GO MAKE THESE.
THE PUMPKINS
ARE ALMOST GETTING DONE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
IT TASTES JUST LIKE PUMPKIN PIE.
YEAH.
GREAT FLAVOR, DELICIOUS.
IT'S, LIKE, PUMPKIN BREAD
WITH A LITTLE CRUST ON IT...
YEAH.
LITTLE CRISP.
DEFINITELY UNIQUE
AND VERY TASTY.
SUNDAY MORNING WE ARE RIGHT HERE
HAVING OUR PANCAKES.
IT'S VERY NICE.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
OF COURSE?
IT'S BREAKFAST HEAVEN.
HOW WAS YOUR BREAKFAST?
VERY FABULOUS.
WHEN YOU WALK IN THE DOOR,
THEY KNOW YOU.
HEY, HOW YOU DOING?
IT'S ALMOST LIKE YOU'RE IN
SOMEONE'S KITCHEN EATING.
A BUNCH OF OUR CUSTOMERS
CAME IN
AND SAID THEY WANTED
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
HERE'S YOUR RASPBERRY.
AND ENJOY.
SO I CAME UP
WITH THIS RECIPE.
RASPBERRY FRENCH TOAST.
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH FOUR EGGS,
LITTLE BIT OF MILK,
VANILLA.
YOU GUYS AREN'T SUBTLE ON FLAVOR
IN THIS HOUSE.
NO, WE LIKE
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
TO THE SIDE.
'CAUSE NOW THIS
IS CREAM CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA WHIP THIS
UNTIL IT'S NICE AND SMOOTH.
POWDERED SUGAR--
JUST--I WILL--COME HERE.
I KNOW YOU AND YOUR FAMILY
AND MIXERS.
I DO IT SLOW.
WE'VE GOT
SOME RASPBERRY JELLY.
IT TASTES LIKE SUGAR FUEL.
I HAVE ONE MORE INGREDIENT--
CORN FLAKES.
OH. SILLY RABBIT.
FIRST YOU TAKE SOME BUTTER,
SLAP IT DOWN ON YOUR HOT GRILL.
THAT IS THE MIXTURE OF
THE VANILLA, EGGS AND THE MILK.
DUNK IT IN MY CORN FLAKE
MIXTURE, BOTH SIDES,
SLATHER 'EM UP.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU'RE DOING THIS.
SOON AS I FLIP IT,
I CUT IT.
TAKE THE FRENCH TOAST OFF.
WE HAVE
MY RASPBERRY FILLING.
SLATHER ON THE GOODNESS.
THEN SECRET SAUCE.
WHAT'S IN THAT?
IT'S RASPBERRY JELLY.
SHH.
DRIZZLE THAT
RIGHT DOWN THE TOP.
WOW. THE CRUNCH
OF THE FRESH TOAST IS MONEY.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A JELLY DONUT EXPLODED.
I MEAN, I'M SHAKING JUST FROM
EATING THAT FIRST SEVEN--
SEVEN BITES.
IT IS VERY GOOD.
IT'S LIKE DESSERT.
THE FOOD IS JUST WONDERFUL.
'CAUSE IT REALLY
IS FAMILY COOKING.
JUMBOT'S UP.
LIKE THIS VICKI SPECIALTY...
IT'S WONDERFUL.
FOLKS ARE PILING IN FOR,
INCLUDING MY FOLKS...
THIS IS WHAT YOUR GREAT UNCLE
USED TO MAKE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
I NEED THE RASPBERRY FRENCH
AND A FULL PUMPKIN.
APPLE-CINNAMON HOTCAKES
COMING OUT.
THE DOR-STOP IN THE DORMONT
SECTION OF PITTSBURGH...
OKAY.
IS A FAMILY JOINT...
NICE TO SEE YOU GUYS.
THAT'S BEEN TURNING OUT
FAMILY BREAKFAST
FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS.
I COME HERE WITH FAMILY
AND FRIENDS A LOT.
IT'S NICE TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE
BREAKFAST WITH YOUR FAMILY,
AND, BY THE WAY,
THIS IS MY FAMILY.
THIS IS MY MOM PENNY,
MY DAD JIM, MY AUNT POLLY,
MY COUSIN TOM AND JODI.
AND THEY'RE HERE
FOR VICKI LAWHORNE'S
FAMILY FAVORITES, LIKE...
MY MOM'S JUMBOT.
YOU HEARD HER--
IT'S CALLED JUMBOT.
EVERYTHING
ALL MIXED TOGETHER,
AND IT'S JUST
AWESOME-TASTING.
IT'S GOT TOMATOES, ONIONS,
GREEN PEPPERS,
PRETTY MUCH ANYTHING YOU WOULD
WANT IN A BREAKFAST, IT HAS.
LET'S GO.
YOU TAKE
WELL-DONE HOME FRIES,
RAW ONIONS...
GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
TOMATOES,
ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
YEP.
HOT PEPPERS.
THAT'S ONE ORDER?
FOR YOU.
WOW.
EGGS.
YOU MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
I LIKE IT.
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'VE SEEN IT
WITH THE HOT PEPPERS IN IT
LIKE THAT.
OH, IT'S GOOD.
CHEESE.
PILE IT ON TOP.
GOT A LITTLE METHOD
TO THE MADNESS HERE.
AND THAT'S THE JUMBOT.
MMM.
LIKE IT?
OH, THAT IS GREAT.
WOW, THAT'S A SPICY DISH.
MM-HMM.
UH-HUH.
THEY TOLD ME YOU LIKE HOT--
REALLY HOT STUFF.
OH, I DO.
THOSE AREN'T MILD PEPPERS.
AND THE SAUSAGE
ISN'T REAL PETITE EITHER.
THAT'S A GREAT MEAL.
GOOD.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
HERE'S YOUR JUMBOT.
LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
MY DAD WOULD LIKE THIS.
THAT'S SOUNDS GREAT.
SHARE IT WITH YOUR DAD.
SHARE IT WITH MY DAD?
NO, HE CAN ORDER HIS OWN.
SURE. OH, OKAY.
THIS IS WHAT YOUR GREAT UNCLE
USED TO MAKE.
HE ONLY HAD ONE SKILLET,
AND HE MADE EVERYTHING IN IT.
EVERYTHING FIT
INSIDE OF IT?
YES.
DID YOU GET
A HALF PORTION, DAD,
OR DID YOU ALREADY--
NO, I ATE
THE OTHER HALF.
I ATE THE OTHER HALF
WAITING FOR YOU.
AND I DIDN'T GET
AN OUNCE OF THING ON YOU.
THAT'S THE AMAZING PART.
NO FOOD,
TOTALLY AMAZING.
WE'RE RAVING FANS.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
BANANA OATMEAL.
JUST CONTINUE COMING BACK.
IT'S LIKE COMING HOME.
(man) IT'S GOT CHARACTER.
IT'S GOT GOOD FOOD.
YOU CAN'T ASK FOR MORE.
WE HAD TOFU EGGS
IN CALIFORNIA.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING, MOM?
PUTTING TABASCO.
YOU THINK
YOU'LL FEED HIM, TOO?
MY FAMILY--LITTLE MILD GLIMPSE
INTO THE LIFE AND REALITY
OF WHY THIS IS SUCH
A WEIRD SHOW.
WHOO-WOO.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE "D."
REALLY HOT.
HOT?
HOT, BUT GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
PEOPLE EAT ALL THAT?
MM-HMM.
(mumbling)
UH-HUH.
YOU WANT IT?
NOPE.
ARE YOU SURE?