HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) WHOA-HO!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(woman)
SLICE IS UP.
REAL-DEAL ITALIAN...
LOOK AT THAT!
IN PITTSBURGH...
CACCIATORE,
SPAGHETTI, MEATBALLS.
A FAMILY JOINT...
LASAGNA'S DONE.
WHERE NOTHING'S CHANGED...
WHAT YEAR ARE WE
TALKIN' HERE?
1944.
FOR MORE THAN 60 YEARS...
DELICIOUS.
AND EVEN THE RAVIOLI
IS MADE BY HAND.
TENDER, THE TEXTURE'S
PERFECT.
IN SAN DIEGO...
BY FAR, THIS IS
MY FAVORITE PLACE TO COME.
THERE'S SO MANY DIFFERENT
TYPES OF PIZZA.
A CALIFORNIA TAKE...
I JUST LOVE
THE SAUCE.
ON NEW YORK PIZZA...
DONATELLO.
MADE BY A GUY WHO'S
A REAL-DEAL ITALIAN.
I WAS RAISED
IN NORTHERN MILAN.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A MONA LISA.
MMM! THIS IS AWESOME.
AND IN BALTIMORE...
WHEN I WALKED IN,
I COULD SMELL IT.
THE MARKET WITH A MENU...
HERE YOU GO.
OF HOMEMADE CLASSICS.
THE ARANCINI--I'VE NEVER
HAD IT LIKE THIS BEFORE.
AND THEY'RE EVEN DOIN'
THEIR OWN MOZZARELLA.
MOZZARELLA
IS SO FRESH.
MMM, IT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
THIS IS THE BEST.
LOOK AT THE PORTIONS.
THEY GIVE YOU THE PORTIONS
ON HOW BIG YOU ARE.
LOOK HOW--YEAH.
IS THAT WHAT YOU DO--
YOU SCALE IN?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO 64 YEARS AGO,
AN ITALIAN IMMIGRANT
NAMED ROSS ROWE
OPENS A HOT DOG STAND
WEST OF PITTSBURGH.
NOW HE STARTED TO ADD
SOME ITALIAN FOOD TO THE MENU,
AND TODAY, LoBello's
IS A LOCAL LEGEND.
NOW THEY'RE NOT SERVING
HOT DOGS ANYMORE, BUT THAT'S
BECAUSE OF ALL THE KILLER
HOMEMADE ITALIAN DISHES
THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT.
I GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
HERE'S YOUR MEAT RAVIOLI.
IT'S LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER'S COOKING.
CACCIATORE, SPAGHETTI,
MEATBALLS.
LASAGNA'S DONE.
IT'S JUST GREAT FOOD.
YOU'VE HAD IT ALL.
OH, HAD IT ALL AND SOME.
IF YOU WANT A GOOD ITALIAN DISH,
YOU COME HERE.
AND THEY'VE BEEN COMING
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
YOUR DAD STARTED THIS.
IN 1944. I WAS 14.
AND ROSE LoBELLO'S
BEEN HERE EVER SINCE.
SO IT STARTED OUT SELLING
HOT DOGS HERE.
STARTED OUT.
HE THOUGHT, WELL,
WE'LL JUST PUT IN
GNOCCHIS AND RAVIOLIS.
AMAZING.
AND THEN THE RAVIOLIS
AND GNOCCHIS
TOOK OFF LIKE CRAZY.
YEAH?
SO HERE WE ARE.
HEY, BEN...
WITH THE THIRD GENERATION
IN THE KITCHEN...
RO, PUT SOME OIL
IN THAT SAUCE FOR ME.
ROSE'S KIDS ROSALIE...
THE OIL'S
NOT HOT ENOUGH.
AND BEN.
WE NEVER CHANGE
ANYTHING HERE.
THE FOOD STAYS THE SAME--
THE GOOD QUALITY,
THE GOOD TASTE.
YOU KNOW,
WHEN YOU'RE AN ITALIAN,
YOU GO WHERE HOMEMADE PASTA
AND HOMEMADE SAUCE.
THE RAVIOLI'S KILLER.
'CAUSE IT'S STILL MADE
ON THE SAME EQUIPMENT
THEY'VE BEEN USING
FOR HALF A CENTURY
FROM THE SAME RECIPES.
TAKE SOME GROUND MEAT.
GROUND BEEF.
YEAH. SO THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME SEASONED BREADCRUMBS,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT MORE SEASONING--
PARSLEY, PEPPER,
ONION POWDER, GARLIC POWDER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER.
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS IN
WITH OUR HANDS.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS, AND WE'RE
GONNA MAKE A LITTLE BALL.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
WHEN YOU'RE BACK HERE
MAKING TEN HUNDRED THOUSAND
MINI MEATBALLS?
IT'S A TOUGH JOB,
BUT SOMEBODY'S GOTTA DO IT.
OKAY, SO WE'RE MAKING
SOME DOUGH.
YEAH, I'M GONNA TAKE
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
I'M GONNA POUR THE WATER
IN HERE.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT
WITH A BARBECUE FORK.
THIS IS
AN ITALIAN MIXER.
SO THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
GONNA CALL THAT ONE.
AN ITALIAN MIXER, YEAH.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA START
MIXING IT WITH OUR HANDS.
OKAY, IT'S GETTING TO THE POINT
WHERE I CAN DUMP IT
ON THE BOARD.
YOU JUST KEEP MIXING IT.
NOW THAT I HAVE IT
ALL MIXED WELL...
I MEAN, THAT IS
SOME KNEADING, DUDE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I KNOW.
FEEL THE HEATERS ON THIS GUY
WITH ALL HIS SWEAT.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT DOWN
SO WE CAN KNEAD THE DOUGH
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA SEND IT
THROUGH THE SHEETER.
WHAT YEAR ARE WE
TALKIN' HERE?
1944.
SERIOUSLY.
CAN YOU IMAGINE HOW MANY MILES
OF PASTA THIS HAS DONE?
I'D SAY A MILLION.
(making whirring noise)
YOU'RE GOOD AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA DO ANOTHER ONE.
YOU NEED A TOP
AND A BOTTOM TO 'EM.
ONE MORE TIME, THEN WE'RE
GONNA GO DOWN THE LINE.
THIS IS TO MAKE
12 RAVIOLI.
12 RAVIOLIS.
YEAH, I GOTTA
GET YOU
THE ELECTRIC VERSION
OF THIS, BROTHER.
YEAH, WE LIKE IT
THIS WAY, THOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA FLOUR THE BOTTOM.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT ON LIKE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA CUT THE ENDS OFF,
AND WE'RE GONNA
TUCK THESE UNDER--
A TRICK MY MOTHER TAUGHT ME.
SO IT DOESN'T
CAVE IN ON ITSELF.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THE FILLINGS
IN. WE PUT THIS DOWN,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
LIKE THIS WITH OUR HANDS,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ROLL IT STRAIGHT,
LEFT SIDE TO RIGHT SIDE.
IF I GO LIKE THIS,
THEY SHOULD FALL RIGHT OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO NOW LET'S COOK 'EM?
10 TO 15 MINUTES--
WHEN THEY FLOAT,
BASICALLY THEY'RE DONE.
WE SERVE 'EM WITH A RED SAUCE.
THERE YOU ARE.
MMM, DELICIOUS--
GOOD MEAT FLAVOR.
I REALLY LIKE THE THICKNESS
OF THE RAVIOLI.
THAT'S ONE OF OUR
SIGNATURE ITEMS.
LOOK AT THAT.
I COULD EAT THESE ALL DAY.
THIS IS THE BEST MEAT RAVIOLI
I THINK I'VE EVER HAD
IN MY LIFE.
THANK YOU, HONEY.
HOW'S THE RAVIOLI, SIR?
IT'S EXCELLENT. IT TASTES
LIKE MOM'S KITCHEN.
I LOVE ITALIAN FOOD,
AND ESPECIALLY THE ITALIAN FOOD
FROM ROSE.
AND ROSE HERSELF.
WE LIKE TALKIN' TO HER.
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
YOU JUST WANT TO CALL HER
"GRANDMA" WHENEVER YOU COME.
YOU'RE MY ANGEL.
IT'S JUST SPECIAL
ALL AROUND.
I HAVE SUCH GREAT FRIENDS
AND GREAT CUSTOMERS.
GENERATIONS OF 'EM...
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
SINCE I WAS A KID.
I BRING MY DAUGHTER,
BRING MY GRANDSON.
WHOA!
LEAVIN' THEIR MARK.
WHAT GOES ON HERE
WITH THESE BOOTHS?
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO CARVE
THEIR NAMES IN 'EM?
NO, THEY WEREN'T
SUPPOSED TO.
ALL THESE YOUNG KIDS
LOVE COMIN' IN HERE.
THEY WOULD ALL CARVE
THEIR NAMES.
I'M NOT GONNA
SCRAPE 'EM OFF.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
IT'S PART OF THE HISTORY.
THAT'S THEIR NAME.
MY BROTHER'S NAME
IS IN THE BOOTH BACK THERE.
YOU KNOW THE BOOTH
THAT YOU'RE ON.
DESIREE, YEAH.
IT'S TRADITION.
AND IF IT AIN'T BROKE,
THEY DON'T FIX IT.
(Guy)
FUN LITTLE MACHINE.
YOU NEVER FIND THIS KIND
OF HOMEMADE FOOD ANYWHERE ELSE.
CLASSIC ITALIAN,
FROM GNOCCHI...
THEY'RE GOOD.
TO LASAGNA
AND A KILLER MEATBALL SUB.
AND THE SAUCE--
DONE WITH A TWIST
ROSE'S DAD CAME UP WITH.
(Guy)
THAT MUCH OIL?
THE MORE OIL AND ONIONS,
THE BETTER.
AS SOON AS THEY'RE TRANSLUCENT,
THEY'RE READY TO GO IN.
I LIKE IT.
I MEAN, IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT'S REALLY WHAT GIVES
THE SAUCE
THE SIGNATURE FLAVOR.
LATE BREAKING NEWS--
THERE WAS AN OIL SPILL
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
THIS'LL SIMMER FOR
ABOUT THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
LOOK HOW DEEP AND RICH
THE COLOR IS.
I GOTTA TELL YOU--
REALLY NICE. MMM.
I COULD GET IN THAT POT.
VERY OLD-SCHOOL.
JUST LIKE THIS CLASSIC ITALIAN
COMFORT FOOD
YOU DON'T FIND MOST PLACES.
PASTA FAZOOL.
BEANS, PASTA,
A LOT OF GOOD SPICES.
JUST REALLY THICK
AND REALLY FULL OF FLAVOR.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
MAKING THIS?
ABOUT 30 YEARS.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF COOKING
SPRAY ON THE BOTTOM...
OKAY, THAT'S NEW.
SO THAT THE NOODLES DON'T STICK.
THIS IS MY MOTHER'S SECRET.
OKAY.
THEN THE NEXT THING
YOU PUT IN IS WATER...
OKAY.
BAY LEAF, DITALINI.
SO THIS IS--
EVERYBODY IS GOING IN THE POOL
ON THIS.
EVERYTHING
GOES IN TOGETHER.
BEANS.
KIDNEY BEANS. WE USE
OUR RED SAUCE IN HERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
OREGANO, BLACK PEPPER.
BLACK PEPPER.
ONION AND GARLIC.
THAT IS REALLY IT.
OKAY, SO JUST LET IT
SIMMER 20 MINUTES?
20 MINUTES.
SO THIS IS DONE. AND YOU DON'T
SERVE IT JUST LIKE THAT?
NO, THERE'S ONE MORE STEP.
TAKE OIL AND PUT
YOUR GARLIC POWDER IN THERE
AND BROWN
THE GARLIC POWDER.
BROWN THE GARLIC POWDER.
OKAY. THAT'S A NEW ONE.
IT KIND OF, LIKE, BECOMES
NUTTY FLAVORED.
SMELL THAT?
MM-HMM.
AND THAT'S DONE.
DISH ME UP.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S NICE AND CREAMY,
AND THE BEANS JUST
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE PASTA'S TENDER.
DO YOU SELL
A LOT OF THIS?
OH, PEOPLE LOVE IT.
AND IT'S SOMETHING
THAT THEY'VE EATEN
WHEN THEY WERE LITTLE KIDS.
EXACTLY.
THAT'D BE GREAT
ON A NICE WINTER... YOU KNOW?
OH, A NICE PIECE
OF CRUSTY BREAD?
NOW YOU'RE TALKIN'.
HOW IS THE PASTA FAZOOL?
IT'S GREAT. IT'S THE BEST
IN PITTSBURGH.
OH, THAT'S DELICIOUS,
LIKE EVERYTHING HERE.
JUST A LOT
OF GOODNESS...
MM-HMM. DEFINITELY.
A LOT OF "MM-HMM."
MM-HMM.
THERE'S EXTRA "MM-HMM"
IN THERE.
IT'S JUST LIKE HOME.
IT'S A LANDMARK.
LET'S PUT IT THAT WAY.
WE LIKE THAT ROSE
IS HERE.
YOU GONNA COME BACK
AND SEE ME AGAIN?
SHE MAKES EVERYTHING
FROM THE HEART.
YOU AIN'T GOING ANYWHERE
FOR QUITE A WHILE.
YOU GOT TOO MANY PEOPLE
THAT LOVE YOU AROUND HERE.
I'M GONNA BE HERE
ANOTHER 63 YEARS.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
IT'S THE ONLY REASON
I'VE LASTED,
'CAUSE I LOVE ALL OF YOU.
WE LOVE YOU, TOO.
THANKS.
I GET TEARS
IN MY EYES.
UP NEXT...
DONATELLO.
WE'RE HEADED TO SAN DIEGO...
THERE'S SO MANY DIFFERENT
TYPES OF PIZZA.
TO TOSS IT...
WHOA-HO!
TOP IT...
(man) SAUSAGE,
PEPPERONI.
AND FINISH IT OFF.
MMM. THIS IS AWESOME.
I'M DOWN HERE IN SAN DIEGO.
NOW MEXICAN FOOD IN THIS AREA
IS ON POINT.
BUT I'M NOT FEELIN'
LIKE MEXICAN FOOD.
I'M THINKIN' PIZZA.
I HEAR THIS IS THE JOINT--
PIZZERIA LUIGI.
18-INCH, THIN-CRUST,
HAND-TOSSED,
NEW YORK-STYLE PIE
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA?
I GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
THESE PIZZAS
ARE JUST DELICIOUS.
THAT'S ALL YOU CAN SAY.
THE SAUCE IS VERY SWEET.
I LOVE THE CRUST.
LOOK AT HOW THIN AND TIGHT
THAT CR--OH!
BEST PIZZA IN SAN DIEGO.
AT A JOINT THAT'S DOING 'EM
UP TO 20 DIFFERENT WAYS...
SPINACH RICOTTA.
PLAIN CHEESE PIZZA.
I REALLY LIKE
THE VEGAN A LOT.
THAT RIGHT THERE--
THAT'S LIKE A PICTURE POSTCARD.
MADE ENTIRELY BY HAND.
I MADE THE FIRST ONE
AT 15.
LIKE BACK IN ITALY,
WHERE LUIGI AGOSTINI WAS BORN.
I WAS RAISED
IN NORTHERN MILAN.
HE CAME TO THE STATES IN '94,
WORKED AT A COUPLE
OF PIZZA JOINTS...
MAKE IT WHITE.
AND THEN TOOK A CHANCE
AND OPENED HIS OWN.
WHAT MAKES YOUR PIZZA
SO GOOD?
WE REALLY PAY ATTENTION
TO THE DETAILS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE PIZZA DOUGH
WITH BOTTLED WATER?
THE WATER IS THE KEY.
IT IS BETTER.
BOTTLED WATER IS CLEARER,
CONSISTENT.
IN NAPLES, THE PIZZA
TASTES A CERTAIN WAY.
IN NORTHERN MILAN, IT JUST
TASTES A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
ALL THE CHLORINE
INSIDE THE WATER,
IT JUST KIND OF
AFFECTED IT.
A LITTLE
DRY ACTIVE YEAST.
THE WATER'S JUST KIND OF
ROOM TEMPERATURE,
SO IT'S GONNA TAKE A LITTLE
MORE TIME FOR THAT TO ACTIVATE
AS OPPOSED TO HAVING
SOME WARM WATER.
THAT'S WHY I ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR ON THE SIDE.
THROW THE SUGAR ON IT.
I LIKE THAT STIRRING IT
WITH THE ARM METHOD.
IT'S OLD-SCHOOL.
WHY DON'T WE PUT THE HOOK ON IT
AND JUST DO THE HOOK THAT WAY?
IT JUST WON'T MIX IT UP
AS WELL.
WE ARE GONNA USE THE MIXER
AT SOME POINT, CORRECT?
SOME TIME TODAY.
AND THEN I ADD THE SALT.
MR. "I'M STIRRING THE WATER
WITH MY ARM IN THE MIXER."
LOOK HOW FAST
HE'S GOT IT GOIN'.
HIGH-GLUTEN FLOUR--THE GLUTENS
ARE WHAT CREATE THIS ELASTICITY,
THE CHEW TO IT,
AND GIVES IT SOME BODY.
IT'S KINDA LIKE A LITTLE
HOME GYM FOR YOU IN HERE,
BETWEEN LIFTING
AND POURING...
I'M WORKING.
JUST DOING--UH-HUH.
10-15 MINUTES?
ABOUT 15 MINUTES,
IT'LL BE READY.
WHERE YOU GOING?
THAT WAY. WE'RE GOING
TO SET IT ON THE TABLE.
LET'S JUST SET IT
RIGHT UP HERE.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA GO AROUND,
A LITTLE DANCE.
WHAT, WE JUST PULL IT OUT
LIKE THIS, HUH, TRY IT?
MMM, THAT WAS GREAT.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
DUDE, SERIOUSLY, TAKING A BITE
OF THAT--THAT'S DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA GO 18 OUNCES.
AND THEN BALL 'EM UP?
SO YOU ROLL 'EM OVER,
MAKE IT NICE AND CLEAN
ON TOP, SPACE 'EM OUT.
AND SO WE JUST SIT HERE AND JUST
KNOCK THESE OUT ALL DAY.
YOU LET 'EM PROOF
A LITTLE BIT MORE,
THEN YOU START TO MAKE PIES
OUT OF IT.
CORRECT. SO AFTER PROOF,
PUT ON THE FLOUR.
SO THAT'S HOW I DO IT.
I COME AROUND THE EDGE.
GO AROUND ONE TIME,
BACK TO THE MIDDLE.
AND THEN I JUST
KINDA, LIKE--
NOW THIS IS
WHERE THE PARTY STARTS.
AND THEN I--
IS THAT YOUR STYLE?
YEAH.
REALLY?
YOU AN THROW 'EM
IN THE AIR...
WHOA-HO!
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
SEE THE BACK OF THE HAND? I'M
NOT EVEN GONNA PLAY THIS GAME.
I CAN THROW IT, BUT NOT 18,
AND NOT THAT WAY,
NOT WITH THE--MY BLING WILL
SNAG IT. THAT WAS BEAUTIFUL.
AND WE'RE ALL SET
WITH THIS ONE.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
A CAPONE...
THE CAPONE IS GREAT
IF YOU'RE REALLY HUNGRY.
A MEAT-LOVER PIZZA.
AND IT IS SO GOOD.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
LET ME SEE
HOW I CAN MAKE IT.
I RUN MY SAUCE HEAVY
TO THE OUTSIDE,
BECAUSE OF THE THEORY
THAT THE PIZZA COMES UP,
DROP BACK ON IT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
JUST FILL OUT AN APPLICATION.
WE'LL SEE HOW IT GOES.
SO THERE'S A FUTURE.
NOW ARE YOU GRATING
THE MOZZARELLA YOURSELF?
YEAH.
SAUSAGE, PEPPERONI.
OKAY, SO A LITTLE MEATBALL
GOES DOWN?
USUALLY A COMBO MEATBALL,
AND WE JUST GRIND IT DOWN.
LOOK AT THE SAUCE PLACEMENT
ON THAT PIZZA.
LET'S SEE
HOW IT COMES OUT.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE
YOUR OVEN SET AT?
525-550.
THERE YOU GO--
SMOKIN' HOT.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
MMM.
THIS IS REALLY GREAT PIZZA.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
WORK ON THAT CRUST A LITTLE BIT
TO GET A PIECE OFF OF THERE.
OH! YOU'RE COOKIN' IT
IN A HOT OVEN--
THAT'S THE WAY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL WITH THIS.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S GREAT
ABOUT THIS PIZZA?
IT HAS THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF SAUCE UP HERE.
AH, NO WAY!
I'M A MEAT LOVER. WHEN YOU TASTE
THE MEAT, IT'S JUST PERFECT.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST PIZZAS
THEY HAVE HERE.
(woman) SLICE IS UP.
THERE'S SO MANY DIFFERENT TYPES
OF PIZZA THAT YOU CAN HAVE.
TOMATO-BASIL
IS REALLY GOOD.
ONE SAUSAGE
AND BELL PEPPER.
THE MONA LISA--
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A MONA LISA.
IT'S SAUSAGE, PEPPERONI,
MUSHROOMS, ONIONS, PEPPER
AND BLACK OLIVES.
LOOK AT THAT!
A LITTLE CURL...
MMM, THIS IS
SOME OF THE BEST PIE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK AT THE CRUST ON THAT THING.
I MEAN, JUST PERFECT.
I'M MOVING IN YOUR HOUSE.
I'LL SLEEP IN THE KID'S
ROOM. THIS IS AWESOME.
EVERYONE LOVES THE PIZZA.
I THINK THE SAUCE
IS EVERYTHING.
YOU CAN TELL THEY PUT
A LOT OF WORK INTO IT.
(Guy)
GROUND TOMATOES.
(Luigi)
RED PEPPER FLAKE.
THIS IS GREEK OREGANO.
THE GREEK OREGANO
IS A LOT MILDER
THAN THE MEXICAN OREGANO.
MEXICAN.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
BLACK PEPPER.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
THIS IS PARMESAN CHEESE.
I LOVE THIS IDEA.
MIX IT UP NICELY.
THEN THROW THE BASIL INSIDE.
TRY THIS ONE.
NICE--NICE BRIGHT FLAVOR,
GOOD TOMATO, GET THE HERBS.
I MEAN, THIS HASN'T
EVEN STARTED
TO REALLY PULL OUT OF THAT
BASIL AND THAT OREGANO YET.
I JUST LOVE
THE SAUCE.
AND NOT JUST
THE RED SAUCE,
THERE'S PESTO
AND EVEN A BARBECUE SAUCE.
BARBECUE CHICKEN--
THE BEST HERE.
DONATELLO.
OR NO SAUCE AT ALL.
SO THIS ONE
IS A WHITE PIE.
IT'S DELICIOUS
AND SIMPLE.
MOZZARELLA, PARMESAN.
YEAH.
THROW A LITTLE
FRESH SPINACH ON IT.
THROW FRESH GARLIC ON IT.
OH, TALK TO ME.
NOW WE GET THE RICOTTA CHEESE--
NICE AND CREAMY,
AND HERE'S HOW WE DO IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN IT COMES OUT,
WE'RE GONNA HIT OLIVE OIL
OR ANYTHING ON IT?
NOPE, JUST THIS.
THIS IS HOW YOU PARTY.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
MMM. BITING
THAT SALTY MOZZARELLA,
AND THEN YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SPINACH.
BUT THEN YOU BITE
INTO THE RICOTTA,
AND IT'S NICE AND SWEET.
OH, AWESOME.
IT'S THE COMBINATION
OF THE CHEESES, I THINK,
THAT MAKES IT TASTE SO GOOD.
IF I LIVED IN SAN DIEGO, I WOULD
HAVE A SIGNATURE ACCOUNT HERE.
YOU CAN'T GET PIZZA
ANYWHERE IN SAN DIEGO
THAT'S BETTER
THAN LUIGI'S.
THAT IS GOOD.
BY FAR, THIS IS
MY FAVORITE PLACE TO COME.
UNTIL YOU GET A TASTE OF THIS,
YOU REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHAT GREAT PIE IS.
THIS IS THE BOMB.
I JUST ABSOLUTELY
LOVE THE TASTE.
THAT'S THE BOMB PIZZA.
YEAH, IT IS.
THE THING IS
IS YOU'RE THE REAL DEAL.
THANKS, MAN.
I MEAN, YOU ARE, MAN. I WANT
TO GO TO ITALY WITH YOU.
THAT'S THE ONLY DEAL, OKAY?
I'LL TAKE IT.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB, MAN.
YOU WERE AWESOME.
THANKS FOR COMING.
NEXT UP...
THERE YOU GO.
BALTIMORE...
LOOK AT THAT!
FOR LASAGNA FROM SCRATCH.
THIS IS HOW IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE DONE.
YEAH.
THIS IS WHAT
YOUR MOM SAID.
THAT'S RIGHT.
EVERY BIT OF IT.
OH, MMM.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
WITH A NAME LIKE GUY FIERI,
YOU KNOW I LOVE ITALIAN FOOD.
IF YOU FIND YOURSELF
IN BALTIMORE
AND YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR SOME GOOD ITALIAN,
CHECK OUT THIS--Di Pasquale's--
MAKIN' THEIR OWN PASTA,
DOIN' THEIR OWN MOZZARELLA,
CASIN' THEIR OWN SAUSAGE
AND DOIN' IT OLD-SCHOOL
IN THE BACK OF A MARKET.
IS THAT GONNA BE
FOR HERE OR TO GO?
CAN I HAVE A HONEY HAM?
THANK YOU.
IT'LL BE NUMBER 14.
WHY GET INTO THE RESTAURANT
SIDE OF THINGS?
IT STARTED WITH, "WILL YOU
MAKE ME A SANDWICH?"
SO THEN WE BROUGHT A TABLE
OUT INTO THE STORE...
THERE YOU GO.
AND ADD MORE TABLES
AND MORE TABLES.
AND THAT LED INTO THIS.
A FULL MENU...
DO YOU WANT THAT
HEATED OR COLD?
OF HOMEMADE ITALIAN.
I'M HAVING THE LASAGNA.
THE SPICES, THE SAUCE--
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
THE ARANCINI--I'VE NEVER
HAD IT LIKE THIS BEFORE.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
THE KINDA COOKIN'...
THAT'S GOOD.
JOE Di PASQUALE AND HIS WIFE
SABRINA GREW UP WITH.
I USED WHAT MY MOTHER
AND MY PARENTS HAVE TAUGHT ME,
WHAT MY HUSBAND AND I LEARN
AND PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
VERY AUTHENTIC--
MORE LIKE OLD SCHOOL.
WHEN I WALKED IN,
I COULD SMELL IT,
FROM THE FRESH MOZZARELLA
TO THE SAUSAGE.
THIS IS ALL HOMEMADE.
SO YOU MAKE YOUR PASTA NOODLES
FOR EVERY LASAGNA?
MM-HMM.
NOW WHY DO YOU MAKE
THE MOAT?
WELL, BECAUSE I'M GONNA
SCRAMBLE THE EGG.
WHY NOT SCRAMBLE 'EM
AHEAD OF TIME?
I LIKE DOING IT
THIS WAY.
THIS IS HOW IT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE DONE.
YEAH.
THIS IS WHAT
YOUR MOM SAID.
THAT'S RIGHT.
A POUND OF FLOUR, FIVE EGGS,
A LITTLE SALT AND A LOT OF LOVE.
YES.
THEN ACTUALLY JUST A LITTLE
DRIZZLE OF OLIVE OIL.
JUST ABOUT A TEASPOON?
YES.
YOU WANT TO GET IT TO WHERE IT
JUST STARTS TO FORM TOGETHER
AND THEN GRAB IT OUT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU GONNA LET IT REST?
YES, WE'RE GONNA
LET IT REST.
FOR ABOUT WHAT--
20 MINUTES, 30 MINUTES?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
DO YOU COVER YOURS WITH,
LIKE, A LITTLE DAMP TOWEL?
YES, I DO.
SO IT DOESN'T DRY OUT. THIS'LL
BE ENOUGH TO MAKE OUR LASAGNA?
YES. WE'RE GONNA
QUARTER THIS.
AND KNEAD THEM DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
LET ME PLAY.
OKAY, NOT TOO WIDE.
'CAUSE IT WON'T FIT
IN THE MACHINE.
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
TAKE IT.
LET IT DRAW
THROUGH ITSELF.
AND IT'S A NICE
THICK PASTA SHEET.
NOW FOLD IT
INTO ITSELF.
BACK TO THE PRESS.
CHANGE THE NOTCH.
PRESS AGAIN.
SEVEN TIMES JUST TO GET US
TO THIS STAGE.
THESE'LL JUST GET A CHANCE
TO KINDA HANG OUT A BIT...
THAT'S RIGHT.
UNTIL WE'RE ALL DONE,
AND THEN WE'LL...
YEP.
USE A LITTLE SALTED
BOILED WATER.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL--
GIVE IT ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
I'M JUST GONNA GREASE
THE PAN A LITTLE BIT
WITH SOME BUTTER.
A LITTLE BIT OF MARINARA.
MARINARA THAT YOU MADE.
LOOK AT THE COLOR
ON THAT. MMM.
GO OVER TO OUR
PASTA SHEETS.
LOOK AT THAT.
LAY IT DOWN IN HERE.
RIGHT, AND YOU'RE OVERLAPPING,
BECAUSE THAT HELPS IT
STAY TOGETHER WHEN YOU COME OUT
WITH THE SPATULA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SAUCE,
PARMESAN FIRST.
JUST ADDS A LITTLE BIT
OF SALTINESS TO IT.
THEN I GO
FOR THE GROUND BEEF.
THE FRESH GROUND
THAT YOU DO.
YES.
A LITTLE GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
PARSLEY, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE MOZZARELLA--
LAY SOME OF THAT DOWN.
AND THAT'LL MELT
AND SPREAD A LITTLE BIT.
IT WILL SPREAD OUT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
FOR THE RICOTTA CHEESE.
NICE AND LIGHT.
MM-HMM.
HOW MANY LAYERS
IS THIS--THREE?
THREE SHOULD WORK.
SO WE GO BACK DOWN
WITH THE NOODLES, SAUCE,
PARMESAN, GROUND BEEF,
MOZZARELLA, RICOTTA,
AND THEN AGAIN.
AND AGAIN.
WE BAKE
OPEN ON THE TOP LAYER.
YES, 350
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
FANTASTIC. AHA, LOOK AT THAT.
SEE THOSE LAYERS IN THERE?
OH! MMM!
THAT'S DELICIOUS--EXACTLY HOW
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE DONE.
NOTHING'S POURING OUT.
YOU CAN TASTE THE MEAT.
THE RICOTTA STANDS OUT.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S UP THERE WITH ANY
OF THE BEST LASAGNAS THERE ARE.
GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU.
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH
OF THE FILLING--A LOT OF FLAVOR.
THIS IS WHERE I GET
AUTHENTIC LASAGNA.
ALL THAT THEY SERVE HERE IS
ALL THE TRADITIONAL ITALIAN.
YOU CAN COME HERE AND DO
YOUR GROCERY SHOPPING, ALSO.
NOT ONLY CAN THEY SHOP,
THEY CAN GET A BITE.
THEY GET AN ESPRESSO,
A GLASS OF WINE.
THEY DO EVERYTHING
WONDERFULLY.
I LOVE
THEIR SANDWICHES.
HOMEMADE ITALIAN SUBS
ARE JUST EXCELLENT.
THIS ONE'S STACKED
WITH PROSCIUTTO, CAPICOLLA
AND SOPPRESSATTA.
AND THEY'VE GOT
THEIR OWN SAUSAGE...
YOU CAN DEFINITELY TELL
THAT THIS IS AUTHENTIC
SWEET ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
HANDMADE FROM SCRATCH.
IT REALLY MIXES WELL
WITH THE FRESH MOZZARELLA.
YEP, THEY'RE
DOING THAT FRESH, TOO.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF MOZZARELLA
DO YOU GUYS MAKE A WEEK?
200 POUNDS.
'CAUSE THEY'RE USING IT
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING,
FROM LASAGNA TO SANDWICHES,
AND FOR THE BOCCACCINI--
THE LITTLE ONES
IN CAPRESE SALAD.
IT'S NOT A RECIPE,
IT'S A TECHNIQUE.
YOU HAVE TO MAKE
A LOT OF BATCHES
IN ORDER TO...
TO REALLY GET IT
STRAIGHT.
STARTING OFF
WITH THE CURD.
SMALL BATCH OF CURD.
SUBMERGE THE CURD--
NO SALT OR ANYTHING
IN THIS, RIGHT?
NO.
JUST REGULAR HOT WATER.
YES.
YOU WANT THEM ALL
TO KIND OF SOFTEN UP
AND START TO BREAK DOWN.
YES, AS YOU WORK IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MAKE SURE ALL THE LUMPS
ARE OUT.
OKAY. DIDN'T I SEE THIS
IN "GLADIATOR"?
THE SACRED MOZZARELLA OAR!
WE WANT TO EVENTUALLY
GET IT TO A BALL.
KIND OF LIKE I'M
WORKING PIZZA DOUGH?
YES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
INTO THE SALT WATER?
YES, THIS SOLUTION GIVES IT
A SALTY OUTSIDE,
BUT A SWEETNESS INSIDE.
RIGHT.
IT ALSO HELPS
WITH THE PRESERVATION OF IT.
YES.
COVER THEM, AND THEY SIT IN HERE
FOR ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE EAT THEM.
THE MOZZARELLA IS SO FRESH,
WHEN YOU PULL IT UP,
CHEESE JUST KEEPS COMING.
YOU CAN TASTE
ALL THE FRESH FLAVORS.
THIS IS THE MOZZARELLA
THAT WE MADE.
YOU NEED TO TASTE IT.
MMM. NICE LITTLE SALTY EXTERIOR,
FIRM ON THE INSIDE--
MMM, IT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
DEFINITELY A LITTLE RICHER,
MORE FLAVORFUL.
YOU CAN'T FIND THIS
IN ANY RESTAURANT.
THIS IS
THE REAL-DEAL ITALIAN.
EVERYTHING YOU'D EXPECT...
(man) LASAGNA.
AND A SICILIAN FAVORITE...
MMM.
CALLED ARANCINI...
THE RICE AND THE CHEESE--
IT JUST KIND OF MELTS
TOGETHER--REALLY AMAZING.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
Di Pasquale's IN BALTIMORE
IS A TAKE-OUT DELI...
WHAT KIND OF DRESSING
WOULD YOU LIKE?
TURNED SIT-DOWN JOINT...
THANK YOU.
FOR HOME-COOKED FAVORITES.
I'LL COME HERE,
GET SOME NICE PASTAS,
SALADS AND THINGS
LIKE THAT.
DEFINITELY SOME OF THE BEST
FOOD I'VE EVER HAD.
I'VE NEVER HAD A LASAGNA
LIKE THIS--OUT OF THIS WORLD.
I FEEL LIKE I'M AT--
IN ITALY.
YEAH, ITALY.
OR DOWN AT SICILY,
FOR THIS ONE.
THE ARANCINI--IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S ALL MELTED TOGETHER
AND AMAZING IN THE CENTER.
ARE WE GONNA FRY THESE
OR BAKE 'EM?
WE ARE GONNA FRY THEM.
AH, MY FAVORITE WORD.
"FRY."
NO--"AH."
SO LET'S BEGIN THIS.
THIS IS ACTUALLY
BEEF STOCK.
1/2 GALLON--AND WE
MAKE THAT HERE?
YES, WE DO.
GONNA WAIT FOR THAT TO BOIL.
WE'RE USING ARBORIO RICE...
MM-HMM.
WHICH IS A NICE BIG,
THICK SHORT-GRAIN RICE.
MM-HMM, GREAT TO WORK WITH
WHEN YOU'RE MAKING
SOME KIND OF RICE BALLS,
EASY TO MOLD.
YOU GIVE THIS
A QUICK STIR.
JUST LET THIS SIMMER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHEN ARE WE GONNA
ADD IN OUR INGREDIENTS?
I'M GONNA ADD IN A LITTLE BIT
OF SEA SALT.
OKAY, A LITTLE
WHITE PEPPER.
SOME WHITE PEPPER,
A TEASPOON OF BUTTER.
ALL RIGHT.
WHEN IT'S HALFWAY COOKED...
WE THROW IN THE SAFFRON.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THE SAFFRON CAN'T
LAST THAT LONG...
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU GOTTA PUT IT IN THERE,
LET IT BLOOM AND--BOOM.
WE'LL LET THAT FINISH COOKING,
AND THEN WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN?
LET IT COOL DOWN
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, NOW ARE WE DOING THIS
TRADITIONAL-STYLE?
YES.
I'M LEARNIN' IT
THE RIGHT WAY?
YES. GRAB SOME RICE THERE--
MAKE A LITTLE BALL.
LITTLE?
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO PRESS DOWN ON IT,
MAKE, LIKE, A LITTLE WELL
IN THERE.
MY WELL OF FRIENDSHIP, THIS.
SURE. WE'RE GONNA GRAB
A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS GROUND MEAT MIXTURE
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
BEEF AND PORK
WITH MARINARA AND VEGGIES.
A LITTLE MOZZARELLA...
MM-HMM.
NOW WE'VE GOTTA BRING THE TOP
OVER, SO WE KINDA GET--
RIGHT.
SO THAT GETS BURIED
IN THE CENTER.
THEN YOU'RE GONNA DIP IT
IN YOUR LITTLE FLOUR AND WATER.
THEN INTO THE BREADCRUMBS...
THAT'S RIGHT.
JUST PUTTING A CRUST ON 'EM.
YES.
350-DEGREE OIL?
OKAY, AND THEN WE'LL SERVE 'EM
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF THIS
WARM MARINARA
OR TOMATO SAUCE.
MARINARA SAUCE, MM-HMM.
JUST TILL THEY'RE
NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
WHICH ONE DO YOU LIKE?
I THINK
THAT ONE'S PERFECT.
OKAY. OH!
LOOK AT THAT.
PRETTY.
THE MELTED MOZZARELLA--
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
POUR A LITTLE SAUCE OVER IT.
MMM! IF I WAS TAUGHT
HOW TO MAKE THOSE AT HOME,
I NEVER WOULD'VE LEFT HOME.
THE RICE HAS GOT A NICE
LITTLE FIRM CENTER TO IT...
MM-HMM.
BUT A NICE CREAMINESS
ON THE OUTSIDE. MMM! MMM!
THAT IS JUST FANTASTIC.
I LOVE THE PEAS IN THERE, TOO.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S IT RIGHT THERE--WINNER,
WINNER, RICE BALL DINNER.
FIRST THING THAT HITS ME
IS THE CRISPINESS
OF THE OUTER CRUST.
THE MEAT AND THE RICE
AND THE MOZZARELLA
ALL BLEND TOGETHER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
ONE MEAT LASAGNA.
THE BEST HOME-COOKED
ITALIAN MEAL YOU'LL EVER HAVE.
ON A SCALE OF 1 TO 10,
I'D GIVE IT A 12.
IN THE WORLD
OF BALTIMORE ITALIANS,
IS THIS
ONE OF THE BEST?
THIS IS THE BEST.
(man) I WOULD RECOMMEND IT
TO EVERYBODY.
IT HAS AN AUTHENTIC
ITALIAN FEEL.
LOOK AT THE PORTIONS.
THEY GIVE YOU THE PORTIONS
ON HOW BIG YOU ARE.
LOOK HOW--YEAH.
IS THAT WHAT YOU DO--
YOU SCALE IN,
AND THEN THEY
SERVE YOU?
RIGHT, YEAH!
I DON'T COME BACK HERE
JUST FOR THE MOZZARELLA
AND THE PASTA AND THE SAUSAGE
AND THE WHOLE THING,
JUST TO HANG OUT
WITH THESE CATS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
BUT WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE "D."
TRY IT.
MMM, THAT WAS GREAT.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
I LIKE THE SALT IN THAT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
HEY!
WHOA!