HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHAT IN THE--
IS NOT WHAT YOU'D EXPECT...
IT'S A TOTAL
HOLE IN THE WALL.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THE ALBUQUERQUE SHACK...
CHICKEN'S COMING UP.
WHERE THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
FROM SCRATCH...
YOU MAKE
YOUR OWN BUTTER?
RIGHT.
IT'S ECLECTIC FOOD
WITH A NEW MEXICAN TWIST.
LIKE ENCHILADAS
WITH DUCK CONFIT.
TWO LEGS PER ORDER?
YEP.
(whistles)
HE'S FEARLESS.
MMM. LITTLE PLACE--
HUGE FLAVOR.
THIS CHICAGO DINER...
(man) OH,
THE REUBEN'S SPECTACULAR.
DOING IT THEIR OWN WAY.
A DINER WITHOUT A FRYER?
AND THAT MEANS
FRESH SEAFOOD...
(man) THAT'S A GREAT-LOOKIN'
PIECE OF FISH.
16 KINDS.
JUST WHAT YOU EXPECT TO FIND
IN YOUR ALL-AMERICAN DINER.
AND THE AUSTIN JOINT...
YOU HAVE TO COME HERE.
SCRATCH-COOKIN'
AROUND THE CLOCK...
WE'RE OPEN 24/8.
WHERE ITALIAN MEETS CAJUN...
MMM. THAT'S
ON POINT, MAN.
WITH ALL KINDS OF HEAT.
YOU GOT ANY MORE THINGS
WE CAN COOK-BURN?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'VE SAID IT ONCE,
AND I'M GONNA SAY IT AGAIN.
IF YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR THE KILLER FOOD,
YOU'VE GOTTA SLOW IT DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
HERE I AM ON THE OUTSKIRTS
OF ALBUQUERQUE, NEW MEXICO,
ON A LITTLE STRIP OF ROAD
THAT'S GOT A 25-CENT CAR WASH
AND A LITTLE SHACK
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE STREET
CALLED SOPHIA'S PLACE,
WHERE A HANDS-ON CHEF
IS DOIN' THINGS HIS OWN WAY.
MAKE YOUR OWN BUTTER?
RIGHT,
SIT HERE AND CHURN THE BUTTER.
WE DO EVERYTHING BY HAND.
TOMATILLO SAUCE.
NOW WHERE WERE YOU
WORKING BEFORE THIS?
(speaks indistinctly)
ZUNI CAFE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WOW, SOME CREDITS THERE,
BROTHER.
SOME CREDITS THERE.
BUT DENNIS APODACA...
THAT'S READY.
GAVE IT ALL UP FOR THIS.
IT'S A TOTAL
HOLE IN THE WALL.
HE'S COMIN' HOME...
HI, GUYS.
TO COOK FOR HIS FRIENDS.
POBLANO RELLENO.
IT'S ECLECTIC FOOD
WITH A NEW MEXICAN TWIST.
IT HAS A GOURMET
FLAVOR TO IT.
OOH, DELICIOUS.
I HAD THE SHRIMP TAMALE.
THIS IS
THE SCALLOP TACOS.
I DIDN'T DRIVE
BY THIS JOINT
THINKIN' I'M GONNA FIND
A SCALLOP TACO.
NEITHER DID WE.
HE IS THE BEST CHEF.
DUCK ENCHILADAS.
I'VE HAD A LOT OF ENCHILADAS.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE EVER HAD
A DUCK ENCHILADA.
IT'S GOOD?
IT'S GREAT.
OKAY, BROTHER,
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN' NOW?
A TOMATILLO SAUCE
FOR OUR DUCK ENCHILADAS.
OKAY.
TOMATILLOS, SOME OIL,
SALT, PEPPER--
TOSS 'EM AROUND, THEN I'LL
GRILL 'EM AND BLACKEN 'EM.
AT THE SAME TIME, IN THIS PAN
WE'LL PUT THE FOUNDATION
OF THE SAUCE--A LITTLE OIL,
ONIONS, A LITTLE GARLIC.
LET'S TURN THESE OVER.
TURN 'EM AROUND A LITTLE BIT
SO YOU DON'T LOSE 'EM.
AND THEN A LITTLE CHIPOTLE
IN ADOBO...
CHIPOTLE CHILI.
THE RECONSTITUTED,
DRIED, SMOKED JALAPEÑOS
IN A LITTLE BIT
OF A TOMATO-VINEGAR SAUCE.
SO YOU GOT ENOUGH OF A ROAST
ON 'EM. NOW THEY GO IN?
YEP.
I'LL ADD A LITTLE WATER.
SO THEY'LL SIT THERE
AND SIMMER A LITTLE BIT.
EXACTLY.
ONE LAST INGREDIENT--
YOUR HONEY.
THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
LET 'EM COOL,
THEN I'LL MASH 'EM.
AND THEN I'LL LET IT REDUCE
FOR 10 OR 15 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE FILLING
FOR THE DUCK ENCHILADAS.
WE'RE GONNA CONFIT
SOME DUCK?
EXACTLY.
WE SEAR SOME DUCK, PEPPER,
SALT, PUT IT IN A POT,
RENDER DUCK FAT, COOK IT OFF
FOR THREE OR FOUR HOURS.
SO YOU LEAVE IT ON THE BONE
IN THE SKIN
AND BREAK IT DOWN EACH TIME
TO COOK FOR THE ENCHILADAS?
YEP.
TWO LEGS PER ORDER?
(whistles)
YOU TAKE THE MEAT
OFF THE BONE.
THEN WE PUT THIS
ON OUR FLAT-TOP.
AND HEAT IT UP.
SQUEEZE OF LIME, CILANTRO,
GREEN ONION--
WE ADD OUR POTATO SEASONING--
MEXICO RED CHILIES,
SUGAR, CORIANDER AND SALT.
WE MIX IT AROUND A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S ESSENTIALLY DONE NOW.
I'LL GET A COUPLE
CORN TORTILLAS, GET 'EM SOFT.
OKAY, SO THEY'RE PLIABLE.
THEN WE USE
ASADERO CHEESE HERE.
DUDE, THAT'S
A LOT OF DUCK.
THAT IS A LOT OF DUCK.
GET SOME OF OUR TOMATILLO SAUCE.
AND WE TOAST PUMPKIN SEEDS
IN A LITTLE POTATO SEASONING.
SCALLIONS, AND LIKE
EVERYTHING ELSE AT SOPHIA'S,
GARNISH IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF QUESO FRESCO.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
(whistles)
DUDE, THAT IS REALLY GOOD--
I MEAN, REALLY GOOD.
THAT'S AN EXPLOSION OF FLAVOR.
YOU'VE GOT IT GOIN' ON
ON THIS ONE.
I'M SORRY, I'M INTERRUPTING
MY MONOLOGUE HERE,
SHOVING MY FACE WITH IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE KICKER IS
ON THAT? THE HONEY.
IT'S GREAT--
RICH, RICH.
SKILLFUL USE OF FLAVORS.
(woman)
THE FLAVOR'S GREAT.
I GOT IT.
HE'S NOT AFRAID
TO EXPERIMENT.
I LIKE THE BLUE
CORN PANCAKES,
THE HONEY BUTTER
WITH THE PIÑóN, EXACTLY.
PIÑóN--PINE NUT.
PANCAKES ARE
ALL ABOUT BUTTER AND SYRUP.
NOW THIS IS
JUST HEAVY CREAM.
OKAY.
AND WE MIX IT. IT'LL SEPARATE
THE FAT AND THE BUTTERMILK.
YOU STRAIN THAT,
AND THAT'S BUTTER.
WE'LL ADD TOASTED PINE NUTS,
DRIED CHERRIES...
MMM.
AND HONEY.
AND THIS GETS PUT
ON TOP OF THE PANCAKES.
YEP.
REALLY GOOD. THE BUTTER IS
OUTSTANDING. THAT MAKES IT,
ESPECIALLY WITH
THE PINE NUTS IN THERE.
VERY DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
HE'S FEARLESS.
COMING UP.
THE SECRET'S
GETTING OUT.
AND EVERYBODY LOVES IT.
YOU GET A PRETTY
LOYAL FOLLOWING.
OUR CUSTOMERS ARE HERE
THREE OR FOUR TIMES A WEEK.
SHRIMP TAMALE.
YOU NEVER GET
TIRED OF IT.
RIB EYE SALAD.
(woman)
WE JUST CAN'T FIGURE OUT
HOW HE MAKES
THIS WONDERFUL FOOD...
BACK UP.
FROM THAT
LITTLE SIMPLE KITCHEN.
BUT AS I LOOK AROUND HERE,
WE DON'T HAVE AN OVEN.
NO OVENS, NO BURNERS.
WE JUST USE TWO GRILLS.
AND WHY DIDN'T WE PUT IT
UP HIGHER?
BECAUSE WE HAVE
SHORT STAFF.
WE'RE SHORT-STAFFED? YOU SHOULD
PUT A "NOW HIRING" SIGN OUT.
YOU DON'T HAVE
A FREEZER.
NO.
A TOMATILLO
AND A DRIZZLE OF--
SO THEY'RE BUILDING THE MENU
AROUND WHATEVER'S FRESH.
EVERY TIME YOU COME HERE,
THERE'S A NEW SURPRISE.
WE HAVE ANYWHERE BETWEEN
FIVE AND NINE SPECIALS.
AND THAT CHANGES DAILY.
THIS IS THE ...RELLENO.
WELL, THAT'S EASY
FOR YOU TO SAY.
YES, IT IS.
WHICH IS A POBLANO CHILI
STUFFED WITH SQUASH
AND ONIONS AND CORN.
SIR, WHAT ARE YOU
ENJOYING?
I'VE GOT
THE SHRIMP TAMALE.
DELICIOUS--
IT HAD A LITTLE KICK TO IT.
SO I CAN TAKE IT
FROM THE CORN HUSKS
THAT WE'RE MAKIN' TAMALES.
RIGHT. FIRST I'VE GOTTA
SAUTé SOME SHRIMP.
SAUTé IT
IN A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
RIGHT.
ANY SEASONING IN THERE?
WE ADD
OUR POTATO SEASONING,
GREEN ONIONS AND CILANTRO,
ONE SQUEEZE OF LIME.
A LITTLE LIME?
THAT'S IT.
SO THE MASA--
WE'VE GOT LARD, WHICH IS
REALLY THE WAY I LIKE TO DO IT,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
AND SOME WATER.
AND THAT'S IT.
IS THAT HOW FAR
YOU LAY YOURS OUT?
YEP.
THEN YOU GET
A COUPLE SHRIMP.
NOT LETTIN'
ANY OF THAT GO.
YEAH, THAT'S
THE GOOD STUFF.
AND WE ALSO ADD
SOME ASADERO CHEESE
AT THIS POINT, AS WELL.
I LIKE THAT.
NOW WE ROLL
AND WE TIE IT.
LIKE WE'RE WRAPPIN'
A PRESENT.
LOOK AT THOSE
TWO BAD BOYS.
THERE YOU GO.
POP 'EM IN THE STEAMER.
THEY'LL STEAM IN THERE
FOR ABOUT A HALF-HOUR
OR SO.
THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE HATCH GREEN CHILI
CREAM SAUCE.
THAT'S GONNA BE OUR SAUCE
FOR OUR SHRIMP TAMALES.
HATCH GREEN CHILI--THEY'RE
THE NEW MEXICO CHILI...
RIGHT.
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF THE SEEDS,
BUT THE SKINS ARE TAKEN OFF.
THE STEMS ARE GONE.
LET'S GET IT GOIN'.
FIRST WE GET
SOME OIL IN THE PAN.
AND NOW WE PUT IN ONIONS
AND LET THEM SAUTé.
NOW WE'LL PUT IN
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE ROUX WITH FLOUR.
YEAH,
AND WE WANT IT, LIKE,
CARAMEL COLORED.
OKAY, SO ARE WE
DARK ENOUGH?
YEAH, WE'RE
DARK ENOUGH.
NOW WE GET A LITTLE MILK
IN THERE.
FRESH CORN.
FARMERS' MARKET.
GREEN CHILI.
SO JUST LET THIS
TIGHTEN UP AND REDUCE?
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
I LIKE IT.
THERE YOU GO.
(Guy whistles)
THIS ONE IS YOURS, COMES
WITH A LITTLE BLACK BEAN.
MAKE A NICE LITTLE FAN.
PEEL IT OFF A LITTLE BIT
SO YOU CAN GET TO IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
HATCH CREAM SAUCE,
PUMPKIN SEEDS, GREEN ONIONS.
MMM, WOW.
THAT'S REALLY NICE,
CAPTAIN ECLECTIC.
THE SHRIMP JUST MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
MASA'S THE PERFECT
CONSISTENCY.
NICE AND CREAMY--
THE GREEN CHILI CREAM SAUCE
COULDN'T BE ANY BETTER
FOR IT.
IT HAD
A NICE HOT FLAVOR.
FABULOUS.
ON THE BACK OF YOUR SHIRT
IT SAYS, "EAT HERE, NOT THERE."
IT SHOULD SAY,
"LITTLE PLACE, HUGE FLAVOR."
YOU ALWAYS FIND
SOMETHING GREAT HERE.
A SIDE OF TOMATILLOS.
DENNIS TAKES THE FOOD
TO ANOTHER LEVEL.
HE LOVES
WHAT HE'S DOING.
UNBELIEVABLE.
(Dennis)
BLUE CORN PANCAKES.
BREAKFAST,
LUNCH, DINNER...
IT'S THE WHOLE
ENCHILADA...
THE WHOLE ENCHILADA.
NO PUN INTENDED.
THIS IS THE KIND OF PLACE--
I THINK IF SOMEONE STOPS,
SLOWS DOWN AND PULLS IN,
COME IN TO TRY
SOME OF THIS FOOD--
I MEAN, IT'S OFF THE HOOK.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADIN'
TO CHICAGO...
CAN'T REALLY GO WRONG.
EVERYTHING ABOUT IT--
EXCEPTIONAL.
WHERE 16 KINDS OF SEAFOOD...
(man) BARRAMUNDI, MAHI,
STURGEON, CATFISH.
AND 35 KINDS OF CEREAL...
MIX ANY WAY YOU WANT.
AT A DINER THAT'S
ONE OF A KIND.
YOU KNOW IT'S GOOD
WHEN IT'S JUST DRIPPIN'
DOWN YOUR ARM--MMM.
I'M HERE IN CHICAGO
ON THE NORTH SIDE OF TOWN,
RIGHT UNDERNEATH THE EL,
AT A LITTLE PLACE
CALLED GLENN'S DINER.
NOW IT SAYS "DINER," SO YOU KNOW
THEY GOT THE BASICS COVERED.
BUT HERE'S THE KICKER--
THEY'VE GOT 16 DIFFERENT KINDS
OF FRESH FISH,
AND NOT JUST THE USUAL SUSPECTS.
ONE BARRAMUNDI. MAHI'S UP.
FRUIT SALSA. STURGEON UP.
I'M HAVING THE STURGEON--
EXCELLENT.
MORE KINDS OF SEAFOOD
THAN JUST ABOUT ANY PLACE
IN ALL OF CHICAGO.
YOUR CATFISH.
I HAVE LOCAL FISH--SO EITHER
THE PERCH OR THE CATFISH.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD CATFISH.
(woman)
DINER AND SEAFOOD
DOESN'T REALLY SEEM
TO GO TOGETHER,
BUT THEY DO A GREAT JOB.
'CAUSE GLENN FAHLSTROM'S
BEEN DOIN' BOTH FOR YEARS.
TASTE GOOD? ENJOY.
THIS IS A CULMINATION
OF WORKING IN FISH MARKETS
AND WORKING IN DINERS.
DON, HOW YOU DOIN'?
MORE COFFEE AT ALL?
WHERE COFFEE'S
ON A FIRST-NAME BASIS,
AND THEY'RE BRINGING
THE FISH IN FRESH.
WE GET DELIVERIES
SIX DAYS A WEEK,
AND WE ALSO BUY
DIRECT FROM HAWAII.
WATCH 'EM COMIN'
IN WHILE THEY'RE OPEN,
DELIVERIN' STUFF.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
(Glenn) I WANTED
TO BRING TOGETHER
EVERYTHING THAT I LIKED,
PUT IT ON THE MENU,
SERVE IT THE WAY
I LIKE IT.
(woman) TILAPIA.
WE TRY NOT TO HIDE THE FLAVOR
OF THE FISH.
SO HEAD CHEF DAVID NAJMAN...
WALLEYE'S UP.
IS KEEPIN' IT LEGIT.
YOU CAN HAVE IT BROILED.
YOU CAN HAVE IT PAN-FRIED.
AND YOU CAN HAVE IT GRILLED.
WHERE'S THE FRYER?
NO FRYER.
A DINER WITHOUT A FRYER?
MY FAVORITE IS THE SEA BASS.
I CHOSE THE AUSTRALIAN
SILVER BARRAMUNDI.
BARRAMUNDI YOU DON'T
SEE EVERY DAY.
HOW ARE WE GONNA
PREPARE IT?
WE'RE GONNA DO
A LIGHTLY BLACKENED.
BLACKENING SPICE.
I'VE STARTED A BASE
OF PAPRIKA.
AND YOU ALWAYS GOTTA HAVE SALT,
ALWAYS GOTTA HAVE PEPPER,
GARLIC, OREGANO.
OREGANO.
I LIKE THIS.
SO WE'RE NOT GOING
FOR A SUPERHOT BLACKENING.
WELL, I SEE A LITTLE CAYENNE
SITTIN' UP THERE.
YEAH, ADDING A LITTLE BIT
IN THERE,
SO YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A LITTLE BIT OF A KICK,
BUT YOU DON'T WANT
TO DOMINATE.
AND THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
MY BLACKENING SPICE
AND A LOT OF OTHER
BLACKENING SPICE--
I ADD OLIVE OIL.
OH, SO YOU MAKE IT
A WET RUB.
MAKE IT A WET RUB--
ALL THOSE SPICES
WILL ENHANCE A LITTLE BIT
WITH OLIVE OIL,
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT
STARTS TOUCHIN' HEAT.
WHEN IT'LL ALSO START
TO WORK ITS WAY
INTO THE FISH A LITTLE BIT.
YEP.
WOW, THAT'S A GREAT-LOOKIN'
PIECE OF FISH.
NOW IF YOU WERE GONNA
GIVE SOMEBODY AN EXAMPLE
OF WHAT BARRAMUNDI TASTES LIKE--
I MEAN, ARE WE INTO A SNAPPER?
A LITTLE BIT MORE FIRM.
IS THERE ENOUGH OIL
IN THE FISH TO COOK IT,
OR DO WE HIT IT--
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE CLARIFIED BUTTER.
OKAY.
ONCE YOU GOT THE PAN
NICE AND HOT,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE BARRAMUNDI.
SO WE'LL PAN-FRY THIS ABOUT TWO,
THREE MINUTES ON EACH SIDE?
YEP.
FINISH IT OFF IN THE OVEN,
OTHERWISE YOU'LL GET
TOO MUCH HEAT ON THOSE SPICES
AND THEY'LL ACTUALLY BURN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IS IT READY?
YEAH, IT'S READY. PUT SOME
ROASTED RED-SKIN POTATOES,
PLATE THAT RIGHT ON OVER.
SUPER TENDER
RIGHT THERE.
THAT SHOULD BE
NICE AND JUICY.
AND WE HAVE
A LEMON-HERB BUTTER.
IT'S GONNA BE OREGANO,
BASIL, SAGE AND THYME,
AND A LITTLE LEMON ZEST.
MMM.
GET OUTTA HERE
WITH THE BUTTER, MAN.
I LIKE THAT
BETTER THAN SNAPPER.
BUT LOOK AT THAT--
NOT SUPER FISHY.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
THAT'S A GREAT PIECE OF FISH.
AND IT TAKES THAT SPICE
INCREDIBLY WELL.
I HAD THE BARRAMUNDI--FIRST TIME
I THINK I'VE EVER HAD THAT--
AND IT WAS VERY GOOD.
VERY MOIST
AND FLAVORFUL.
AND JUST ONE OF ALL KINDS
OF SEAFOOD THEY'RE DOING--
16 EVERY DAY--AHI TUNA,
TASMANIAN KING SALMON,
SEA SCALLOPS
AND CATFISH SERVED
WITH CORNBREAD SHRIMP STUFFING
AND A SPICY HOLLANDAISE.
LOOK AT THE AMOUNT
OF JUICE
THAT JUST SITS DOWN
INSIDE OF THAT. MMM.
WOW, THAT'S REALLY NICE.
STUFFING'S BANANAS.
"BANANAS" IS GOOD. THIS IS
SOME REALLY GOOD CATFISH, MAN--
JUST WHAT YOU EXPECT TO FIND
IN YOUR ALL-AMERICAN DINER.
AND IT REALLY IS A DINER.
ENJOY.
HOW'S YOUR STEAK SANDWICH?
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
OH, THE REUBEN'S
SPECTACULAR.
(Guy) REALLY?
IT'S TOP-NOTCH.
WELL, I'M HAVING
THE MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
IT'S A GOOD THICK PIECE,
AND HE MIXES A LOT
OF GOOD THINGS IN WITH IT.
(David) IT'S NOT
A TRADITIONAL LOAF.
INSTEAD OF MEAT LOAF,
IT'S A MEAT PATTY.
I CAN'T EVEN GET
MY HAND AROUND IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU KNOW IT'S GOOD
WHEN IT'S JUST DRIPPIN' DOWN
YOUR ARM. MMM.
WOW, THAT'S TASTY. DOES IT
COME WITH FREE DRY CLEANING?
MMM, THAT'S
REALLY NICE, MAN.
GOOD MORNING, GUYS.
HOW WE DOIN'?
AND IN THE CLASSIC
DINER TRADITION,
THEY'RE SERVIN' UP BREAKFAST
ALL DAY.
ONE OF THE BEST BREAKFASTS
IN TOWN.
FROM CHOCOLATE CHIP PANCAKES
TO 5-EGG OMELETS...
NICE WAY TO START
THE MORNING.
TO CEREAL...
I'LL HAVE A BOWL
OF LUCKY CHARMS, PLEASE.
AND GET THIS--
35 DIFFERENT KINDS.
MIX ANY WAY YOU WANT.
I COULD HAVE LIFE CEREAL
AND LUCKY CHARMS
AND HAVE LUCKY LIFE?
YEAH, THAT'LL WORK.
LUCKY CRUNCHY,
PEBBLE POPS--
CEREAL BAR AT GLENN'S.
(David) SALMON'S READY.
BUT IT'S THE FRESH FISH
THAT REALLY MAKES
THIS DINER DIFFERENT...
THAT'S, LIKE,
THE SPECIALTY.
ONE OF A KIND COMBINATIONS,
LIKE IDAHO RAINBOW BROOK TROUT
WITH BROWN SUGAR PECANS...
SWEET, MOIST, EXCELLENT.
CANADIAN WALLEYE PIKE
IN CRUSHED PRETZEL.
AND GET THIS ONE.
STURGEON?
IT WAS GREAT.
WITH A BACON-MUSTARD-
CREAM SHERRY SAUCE.
SO HOW DO WE START THIS?
WE ADD A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
AND A LITTLE S.P.G.--
SALT, PEPPER AND GARLIC.
THAT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
WE TRY TO KEEP EVERYTHING
SIMPLE AS POSSIBLE.
THIS IS GONNA BE
RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S JUST A LITTLE SLATHER
THAT'S GONNA GO DOWN,
AND THEN IT GOES
TO THE GRILL.
YEP.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT. NICE.
THE SAUCE
IS MADE TO ORDER.
BASICALLY, WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS BACON,
BUTTON MUSHROOMS, DEGLAZE IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SHERRY.
THAT'S A FIRE.
ROLL IT AROUND, EDDIE.
SHERRY'S ALREADY REDUCED,
SO ALL WE NEED
IS A LITTLE ALFREDO SAUCE.
AND THIS BAD BOY'S
READY TO GO?
THAT BAD BOY IS
DEFINITELY READY TO GO.
START ADDING SOME MUSHROOMS
ON THERE.
(Guy) BOY, THAT'S
NICE AND MEATY, HUH?
MMM. MAN, IF THAT DOESN'T
HAVE THE CONSISTENCY
AND THE TEXTURE OF LOBSTER--
NICE SAUCE ON IT.
MY FAVORITE THING
ABOUT THE WHOLE DEAL, THOUGH,
IS THE CHAR-GRILLING.
IT'S THE SEAR.
IT'S THE MARK,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SMOKINESS
THAT IT GETS--REALLY GOOD.
THE SAUCE WITH MUSHROOMS
AND BACON--
IT'S ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
NO MATTER WHAT THEY DO,
THEY DO WONDERFULLY.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
YOU CAN'T REALLY GO WRONG.
EVERYTHING ABOUT IT
IS EXCEPTIONAL.
WHATEVER GLENN'S DOING,
HE'S DOING IT RIGHT.
THIS IS MY PASSION.
THIS IS PROBABLY MY FIFTH
SEAFOOD RESTAURANT
THAT I'VE OPENED.
AND IS THIS THE FAVORITE
SO FAR?
YOU BET.
I LIKE IT. GOOD EATS, MAN.
WANT TO SEE A MAGIC TRICK?
DISAPPEARED.
NEXT STOP, AUSTIN...
"SORRY, WE'RE OPEN"?
A 24/7 JOINT...
OKAY, GUYS,
THE POLENTA...
DOIN' ALMOST EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH.
MMM. OH, THAT'S GREAT.
EVERYBODY AT HOME RIGHT NOW
WISHES THEY HAD
SMELL-O-VISION IN DOLBY.
IF YOU'VE EVER BEEN
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS,
THEN YOU KNOW ABOUT
THE CONGRESS STREET BRIDGE.
IT'S THE ONE ALL THE BATS
LIVE UNDER.
AT NIGHT, LIKE A ZILLION BATS
FLY OUTTA HERE.
IT'S REALLY COOL.
AND A LITTLE FURTHER
DOWN THE STREET
IS SOMETHING ELSE
THAT'S COOL--
A LITTLE 24/7 JOINT
CALLED MAGNOLIA CAFé.
EGGS BENEDICT.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
THEY'VE GOT GREAT FOOD.
BIG BREAKFAST COMBOS.
WHAT SHOULD I TRY?
THE PANCAKES.
THE TEXAS BENEDICT.
RICH AND CREAMY.
EVERY KIND OF OMELET
THAT YOU'VE EVER SEEN.
I LIKE THE JAMBALAYA.
NACHOS, TACOS.
CHICKEN STIR-FRY.
(woman) QUESADILLAS.
POLENTA.
COOKED TO PERFECTION.
AND THEY WERE DOING IT ALL
FROM 7:00 A.M. TO 10:00 P.M...
Y'ALL DOIN' OKAY?
WHEN KENT COLE OPENED
THIS JOINT 20 YEARS AGO.
YOU STILL WORKIN'
ON THE PEPPERS?
BUT THAT WASN'T ENOUGH
FOR THESE FOLKS.
WE'D BE MOPPING AND THEY'D
KNOCK ON THE DOOR.
SO KENT AND GENERAL MANAGER
PETER TREECE...
HEY, JAMES.
TOOK THE PLACE 24/7.
WE'RE OPEN 24/8.
THAT'S WHAT IT FEELS LIKE.
PURE CHAOS.
CONTROLLED, THEY SAY.
(Guy) THE PLACE IS PACKED.
HAS IT ALWAYS BEEN PACKED?
YEAH.
EVERY SINCE ERIC WESTPHAL
STARTED COOKING HERE...
AMBER!
TEN YEARS AGO.
EVERYTHING'S SCRATCH-MADE?
YEAH.
MOST 24/7 JOINTS AREN'T,
LIKE, MAKING EVERYTHING.
THEY MAKE IT.
ROUND THE CLOCK,
AND DOZENS OF SPECIALS.
BLACKENED SALMON.
IT'S REALLY JUICY
AND TENDER.
IT'S SPICY?
MM-HMM, SPICY.
BUT NOT TOO SPICY?
NOT TOO SPICY.
THIS IS
THE BLACKENING SPICE.
IS PAPRIKA THE FOUNDATION
OF YOURS?
IT DOES GIVE IT THE COLOR
WITHOUT MAKING IT
BRUTALLY SPICY.
A TABLESPOON OF CAYENNE,
BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER,
GARLIC AND...
GRANULATED?
ONION POWDER, THYME
AND THEN BASIL.
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE AT.
SO NOW A LITTLE KOSHER SALT?
A LITTLE
OF OUR SPICE MIXTURE.
IT'S A CLASSIC DRY RUB,
NOT WET LIKE THE ONE WE MADE
BACK AT GLENN'S IN CHICAGO.
BUT THE COOKING METHOD
SURE AIN'T CLASSIC.
ARE WE GONNA
TURN THAT OVER?
NO.
UPSIDE DOWN LIKE THAT,
IT TRAPS MORE HEAT UNDERNEATH
AND GETS IT
EVEN MORE INSANELY HOT.
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
HOLY COW!
YOU NEED, LIKE, ONE OF THOSE
NASCAR HAZMAT SUITS.
HAVE YOU ALWAYS DONE IT
THAT WAY?
YEP.
WOW.
I LIKE TO GET PRETTY RARE
WITH SALMON,
ESPECIALLY IF YOU'RE GONNA
CHAR IT UP THIS MUCH.
OKAY, LET ME TRY IT.
THERE'S YOUR BUTTER.
OKAY.
(laughs)
OH, THIS IS GOOD.
YOU GOT ANY MORE THINGS
WE CAN COOK/BURN? THAT'S CRAZY.
THAT'S GOTTA BE
UP IN THE 700, 800-DEGREE
RIGHT NOW.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS JUST OPTIMUM.
MONEY. SPICE ISN'T OVERDONE,
EXTREMELY FLAVORFUL--
THAT'S A GREAT TECHNIQUE.
IT'S REALLY MOIST INSIDE.
IT'S VERY SUCCULENT.
ACTUALLY PERFECT.
AND LOOK AT WHAT THEY'RE
SERVIN' IT WITH.
JAMBALAYA
IN A STUFFED RED PEPPER.
OKAY, SO OIL AND FLOUR
HAVE COME TOGETHER
TO MAKE A DARK ROUX.
ONIONS.
GARLIC, GREEN BELLS--
THOSE ARE SOME MONSTER
NUGGETS OF JALAPEÑO--
SHALLOTS.
GREEN ONION,
ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
GET OUR RICE IN THERE.
AND WE'RE GONNA THROW
A LITTLE TOMATO IN THERE.
THEN WE KNEAD IN A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CAJUN SEASONING.
ADD THE STOCK...
THIS IS THAT STOCK
THAT YOU MADE
WITH SHRIMP SHELLS
AND CHICKEN STOCK.
ONIONS, GARLIC, CELERY,
DICED CARROTS, THYME,
ROSEMARY, PEPPERCORNS,
SHRIMP SHELLS, A LITTLE
WHITE WINE--KINDA SPICY.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD!
THAT STOCK IS MONEY.
CRAWFISH AND CRAB GO DOWN.
COVER IT, 30 TO 45 MINUTES.
PERFECT AMOUNT OF MOISTURE
IN THERE, NICE AND LIGHT,
NOT TOO HEAVY
ON THE SEAFOOD OVERTONE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME
IT'S GONNA GET
ANY BETTER.
BREADCRUMB, PUT IT
IN THE SALAMANDER.
OH, THAT'S GREAT. A LITTLE
TICKLE FROM THE BREADCRUMB,
IT'S GOT A LITTLE CRUNCH. MMM.
THE RED BELL PEPPER MAKES THAT.
THAT'S ON POINT, MAN.
I LIKE THE JAMBALAYA
A LOT.
IT COMPLEMENTS THE SALMON
REALLY WELL. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
HARRIS, PARTY OF TWO.
IT'S A NEAT PLACE.
AND THE FANS
KEEP ROLLIN' IN...
I'VE COME HERE
FOR 20 YEARS.
TWO TO THREE TIMES
A MONTH.
I COME BACK EVERY WEEK.
FOR THE FOOD AND THE FUNK.
(man) WE LIKE THE ENERGY
OF THE PLACE.
YOU HAVE TO COME HERE.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
WE'VE CREATED SOMETHING
THAT'S LARGER THAN US NOW.
IT'S LIKE A CITY.
IT'S LIKE A VILLAGE.
WE'RE PLANNIN' ON,
LIKE, FRIDAY.
WE'RE GOIN' TO MAGNOLIA'S
ON SUNDAY.
WE'RE JUST KINDA
WORKIN' OUR WAY
THROUGH THE MENU
ONE ITEM AT A TIME.
I AM HAVING
THE TEXAS BENEDICT.
WITH GRILLED SAUSAGE
AND HOMEMADE
CHIPOTLE HOLLANDAISE.
A NICE SPICY KICK TO IT.
I LOVE PANCAKES, AND I COME ONCE
OR TWICE A WEEK TO EAT THEM.
CORNMEAL, WHOLE WHEAT
OR BUTTERMILK...
A LITTLE BLUEBERRY DROP.
HOWEVER YOU LIKE 'EM.
WITH PECANS.
JUST BUTTERMILK
AND LOTS OF SYRUP.
GINGERBREAD PANCAKES
WITH BANANAS.
SO GINGERBREAD PANCAKES.
YEAH.
YOU GOT SOME COFFEE,
BUTTERMILK.
SO WE'VE GOT,
LIKE, A REALLY FUNKY
COFFEE MILK RIGHT HERE.
WATER, WE'VE GOT SOME
SALT, BAKING SODA,
BAKING POWDER, CINNAMON,
NUTMEG, GINGER...
WOW, THAT GINGER
IS POPPIN'.
AND CLOVES.
BROWN SUGAR.
EGGS.
A LITTLE LIQUID CHICKEN?
FLOUR.
I ONLY HAVE
ONE SHIRT TODAY.
GONNA DO THE BUTTER.
DON'T WANT IT TO NOT BE...
THAT'S GOOD. DYNAMITE.
I THINK IT'S GREAT FLAVOR.
I THINK IT'S GONNA BALANCE OUT
NICE. LET'S GO MAKE SOME.
IS THIS A BIG SELLER?
HUGE SELLER, ACTUALLY.
BANANAS.
LIKE A BIG
GINGERBREAD COOKIE.
THAT IS
A REALLY GOOD PANCAKE,
AND WITH THE BANANA, IT'S GREAT,
BECAUSE IT'S NOT SO SUPERSWEET.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A SAVORY PANCAKE.
THEY'RE GOOD.
THE BEST PANCAKES
I'VE EVER EATEN.
THERE'S SUCH A VARIETY.
YOU CAN MIX IT UP.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GET MANY OTHER PLACES.
LIKE TEXAS BENEDICT...
EGGS FLORENTINE.
OR THIS ONE.
OKAY, GUYS,
THE POLENTA...
TOPPED WITH HOMEMADE RAGOUT...
CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE,
CREAMY ON THE INSIDE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
THAT'S MAGNOLIA
MAGNIFICENT.
WE'D LIKE TO THANK EVERYBODY
FOR CHOOSING MAGNOLIA CAFé.
IF YOU'RE WAITING FOR A TABLE,
YOU CAN WAIT INSIDE
OR OUTSIDE OR NEXT DOOR.
(Guy) MAGNOLIA CAFé
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
IS A 24/7 LOCAL FAVORITE...
Y'ALL DOIN' OKAY HERE?
VERY WELCOMING,
VERY NICE.
WHEN YOU THINK OF AUSTIN,
THIS IS A PLACE
YOU WOULD TELL SOMEONE
TO COME.
WHERE CHEF ERIC WESTPHAL'S
DOIN' ALMOST EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH...
THE MENU IS
SO ECLECTIC.
FROM PANCAKES
TO BLACKENED SALMON
TO JAMBALAYA TO HOMEMADE
POLENTA TOPPED WITH RAGOUT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN', DUDE?
WE ARE MAKING POLENTA.
SO WE'VE GOT THE OLIVE OIL,
THE SHALLOTS, A LOT OF GARLIC,
SUN-DRIED TOMATOES.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT THE WATER IN.
THAT'S THE BABY RIGHT THERE.
THESE ARE PRESERVED LEMONS.
SERIOUSLY, YOU MAKE
PRESERVED LEMONS?
OH, YEAH.
IT'S LIKE
A MOROCCAN THING, YEAH.
TAKE THE LEMONS
AND SALT 'EM DOWN.
IT'S A 24-HOUR JOINT
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
RIGHT DOWN
FROM THE BAT BRIDGE,
AND THEY MAKE PRESERVED LEMONS.
WE'RE IN IT TO WIN IT.
I'VE GOTTA TASTE IT. IT GIVES
YOU A REAL GREAT LEMON FLAVOR...
HMM.
ADDS A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT INTO IT.
A COUPLE TABLESPOONS
OF THAT IN.
WHITE WINE.
YELLOW POLENTA,
WHICH IS YELLOW GRITS.
YEAH.
A LITTLE SIMMER GOIN'--
STIR THOSE IN.
A LITTLE HEAVY CREAM--
THAT'LL ADD A NICE LITTLE
CREAMY ELEMENT TO IT. MMM.
JUST PUT SOME IN MY HAND.
POLENTA? AS SOON AS IT
COOLS DOWN, IT'LL SET UP.
WE'RE GONNA
MAKE SOME RAGOUT.
TO GO ON TOP
OF OUR MONEY POLENTA.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME OLIVE OIL THERE,
WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES.
YOU'RE GONNA REALLY CARAMELIZE
THOSE DOWN, THOUGH.
THOSE SHOULD BREAK
INTO THE SAUCE COMPLETELY
BY THE TIME THAT'S DONE.
BY THE TIME
IT'S DONE, YEAH.
ONION. YOU GOT YOUR GREEN.
YOU GOT YOUR RED.
RED WINE FOR A LITTLE ACIDITY,
A LITTLE DEGLAZING FACTOR,
A LITTLE FLAVOR.
ITALIAN SAUSAGE--
THAT'LL BROWN UP,
START TO RENDER DOWN
SOME OF THE FAT OUT OF THAT.
EVERYBODY AT HOME RIGHT NOW
WISHES THEY HAD
SMELL-O-VISION IN DOLBY.
TOMATO ACTION--
WE'VE GOT YOUR CRUSHED,
AND WE'VE GOT YOUR--
CHOPPED.
THERE WE GO.
THIS IS GONNA COOK DOWN
FOR HOW LONG?
UH, USUALLY ABOUT SIX HOURS.
THE SAUSAGE IS
PRIME-TIME SAUSAGE.
IT'S NICE AND SWEET RIGHT NOW,
'CAUSE THOSE PEPPERS AND ONIONS,
THE WAY THE COOK DOWN.
THAT POLENTA--MMM.
SO HOW DO YOU CUT 'EM?
THINLY, JUST STRIPS.
HEAT 'EM UP
ON THE FLATTOP?
YEP.
LAY DOWN ALL YOUR BUTTER.
SO THIS'LL PUT
A LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM
AND HEAT 'EM UP.
PRECISELY.
WE'VE GOT THAT
ALL REDUCED DOWN.
MMM, THAT'S MAGNOLIA
MAGNIFICENT.
THAT IS AWESOME, DUDE.
MMM, I COULD BLOW
THAT WHOLE PLATE IN SECONDS.
SERIOUSLY, TAKE ME AWAY FROM IT
BEFORE I GO INTO A FULL FRENZY.
THE POLENTA WAS AWESOME.
CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE,
CREAMY ON THE INSIDE.
THAT'S PRETTY
DYNAMITE POLENTA.
IT IS.
THE KICKER IS
THE SALTED PRESERVED LEMONS.
REALLY?
YEAH, NO KIDDING.
I'D GIVE IT FIVE STARS.
IT'S NOT LIKE
YOUR NORMAL DINER.
YOU KIDS NEED ANYTHING ELSE?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WE DRIVE AN HOUR
FROM SAN ANTONIO
JUST TO EAT
THE FOOD HERE.
EVERYONE LOVES IT.
SOMETIMES WHEN YOU'RE HUNGRY
FOR SOMETHING
AND YOU KNOW
WHERE THE BEST THING IS,
YOU CAN'T DO WITHOUT IT,
YOU MAKE THE TRIP.
WHO'S THE SMART ALECK
OF THIS PLACE?
"SORRY, WE'RE OPEN"?
HE CAME UP WITH THAT ONE.
YOU KNOW THAT AFTER
PEOPLE JUST SAW
THAT WHOLE POLENTA THING,
THEY'RE BOOKING THEIR TICKETS
TO AUSTIN RIGHT NOW.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THE QUESTION IS--
IS IT SUPER-TENDER-
FLAKEY-FALL-APART-Y?
ABSO-RUTE-RY.