HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THIS TRIP...
THE BEST IN TOWN...
ARE YOU BREATHING
IN THE MIDDLE OF THIS?
(Guy)
IN CALIFORNIA...
(Gorilla)
GOT A THREE-MEAT COMBO
(Guy)
WHERE A GUY NAMED "GORILLA"
BEEF BRISKET!
IS TURNING BRISKET
INTO CHEESESTEAK.
HMM, I MAY HAVE TO GO HOME
AND SHAMPOO MY GOATEE.
IN CONNECTICUT...
BARBECUE HITS FROM EVERYWHERE.
WE HAVE THE EASTERN
NORTH CAROLINA-STYLE,
TEXAS-STYLE BRISKET,
MEMPHIS-STYLE BABY BACKS...
(Guy)
AND CHICKEN DONE HIS WAY.
THESE CHICKENS WERE BRINED
FOR 24 TO 48 HOURS.
OOH, THERE AIN'T NO JOKIN'
THAT BIRD'S SMOKIN'!
(Guy)
AND IN TEXAS...
SMOKY FLAVOR...
(Guy)
RIBS BY THE SLAB...
EVEN SMOKED JAMBALAYA.
JAMBALAYA, JAMBALAYA.
FROM A GUY WHO SWEARS BY
ONE KIND OF WOOD.
GREEN MESQUITE FOR ME
HAD THE BEST FLAVOR,
IT'S BAD ON PITS,
BUT GREAT ON MEAT.
GREEN MESQUITE, HMM,
I'VE SEEN IT ALL.
OH HEAVEN!
IT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪
NOW I PICKED THE WRONG DAY
TO WEAR SHORTS OR DRIVE
THE CONVERTIBLE,
BUT I'M HERE
IN PACIFICA, CALIFORNIA,
TO CHECK OUT GORILLA BARBECUE,
SERVED OUT OF THIS
ORANGE TRAIN CAR,
ORDER UP!
BY THE GUY THIS PLACE
IS NAMED AFTER.
WHERE DID THE NAME "GORILLA"
COME FROM?
FROM MY DAD,
YOU CAN SEE I'M A LITTLE
BIGGER THAN NORMAL...
YEAH, I JUST THOUGHT
IT WAS MY TV.
HEY, IT'S THE FOOD TOO.
GOT A THREE-MEAT COMBO,
BRISKET, HOT LINKS, RIBS,
COMIN' UP...
IT'S SOME OF THE BEST
BARBECUE I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I THINK THE RIBS
AND THE HOT LINKS
ARE OUTSTANDING.
THE BRISKET'S MY FAVORITE.
I KNOW BARBECUE,
I GREW UP IN TEXAS
AND THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
(Guy)
AND IT ALL STARTED
AS A HOBBY...
I'VE HAD THIS VISION
FOR YEARS.
FOR GORILLA, AKA, RICH BACCHI,
AND HIS OLD FRIEND,
JEFF GREATHOUSE.
AND 1/2 POUND OF BRISKET.
WERE YOU GUYS BUDDIES
IN HIGH SCHOOL?
WE WERE, YEAH.
(Guy)
AND AFTER YEARS OF COOKIN'
FOR FRIENDS...
ONE MEAT COMBO, PULLED PORK.
THEY STARTED CATERING.
THIS COMBO'S READY TO ROCK.
(Guy)
THEN...
WE ACQUIRED THE TRAIN CAR
AND HERE WE ARE,
A YEAR AND 1/2 LATER,
ROCKIN' AND ROLLIN'.
GET THIS BAD BOY
FULL OF CHICKEN...
(Guy)
AND DOING IT TOTALLY
FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S TENDER, GREAT FLAVOR.
(Guy)
STARTING WITH GORILLA'S
OWN DRY RUB.
A LITTLE RUB-A-DUB-DUB...
MAKIN' THE DRY RUB.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE GROUND CUMIN,
GROUND OREGANO,
GARLIC POWDER,
GRANULATED ONION,
A LITTLE SALT...
A LITTLE SALT
FROM THE LOVELY SEA,
SOME PAPRIKA,
BROWN SUGAR
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
THEN WE PUT IT INTO
THE MAGIC MIXER,
GIVE IT A MIXEY-MIX...
DID YOU JUST SAY
"A MIXEY MIX?"
IT CAN'T BE GORILLA BARBECUE
AND SAY "MIXEY MIX."
ALL RIGHT, WE'VE GOT
THE SUPER COMBO
SPICE RUB MIX.
THINK THE RUB'S ABOUT READY?
GIVE IT A LITTLE TASTY TASTE?
YEAH, A LITTLE TASTY TASTE
GOES WITH MIXEY MIX.
LITTLE SWEET,
LITTLE BIT OF SAVORY...
AND THEY'RE PUTTIN' IT
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING...
FROM RIBS...
GOT A NICE RUB WRAP.
THE RIBS ARE GREAT!
THERE'S A LOT OF MEAT
ON 'EM.
TO PULLED PORK...
IT'S THE BEST PULLED PORK
I'VE HAD.
TO THIS HEAVY HITTER...
BEEF BRISKET!
TEXAS-STYLE!
THE BRISKET IS AWESOME.
WE'RE GONNA RUB IT,
SLATHER IT ON,
GIVE IT A LITTLE MASSAGE,
FLIP,
THEN START SCOOPING MORE IN,
YOU CAN NEVER HAVE
TOO MUCH RUB ON A BRISKET,
THE FLAVORS ARE RENDERING DOWN
THROUGH THE THICK LAYER OF FAT
THAT'S ON THE TOP.
BRISKET'S READY TO THROW
ON THE SMOKER.
THIS IS THE BABY?
YES, SIR.
OKAY, TURN ON THE EYEBALL
LAMPS UP ON THE CEILING...
'CAUSE SMOKERS ARE
USUALLY DARK AND YOU CAN'T
SEE INSIDE OF 'EM.
YOU HAD THOSE INSTALLED
JUST FOR THAT?
YES.
YOU'RE A GANGSTER.
PICK AND SET,
TOP RACK, 16 HOURS.
SHE'S FIRIN'.
THERE SHE GOES.
NOW, YOU LET THIS REST
ABOUT 1/2 HOUR?
IT PROBABLY MAKES IT
A LITTLE EASIER TO SLICE.
LOOK HOW BEAUTIFUL THAT IS,
LOOK AT THE CRUST ON THAT...
THE SMOKE PENETRATED THROUGH,
GREAT BARBECUE, MAN.
GOOD DRY RUB MIX,
NICE AND TENDER,
THIS IS GREAT!
WE CAN SERVE IT AS
A ONE-MEAT COMBO,
A LA CARTE,
OR YOU CAN GET IT
IN SANDWICHES.
THERE'S A LOT OF BRISKET,
IT'S SMOKED AND IT'S VERY
TENDER.
(Guy)
AND HERE'S ONE YOU DON'T SEE
AT MOST BARBECUE JOINTS.
I'LL GET THE PHILLY CHEESE.
GORILLA'S EVEN USIN' THE BRISKET
FOR A PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
I GOTTA BE HONEST WITH YOU,
BROTHER,
I THINK PHILLY CHEESESTEAKS
NEED TO COME FROM PHILLY.
WELL, LET'S GIVE IT A WHIRL
AND SEE WHAT YOU THINK.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL LET YOU DO IT.
OLIVE OIL, GOT SOME
FRESH CUT VEGETABLES,
ONIONS, BELL PEPPERS,
THE MAGIC RUB...
WE USE IT TO
SEASON EVERYTHING.
GET SOME OF THE FRESH BRISKET,
ADD A COUPLE OF
REAL NICE PIECES.
BARBECUE SAUCE...
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE GOING
WITH IT,
BUT WE GOT SO MANY FLAVORS
IN THERE, DO YOU CALL IT
SOUTHWESTERN PHILLY?
SURE, WE'LL PUT SOME
CHEESE ON THERE,
AMERICAN/SWISS,
PUT A LITTLE LID
ON THERE,
PULL OUR BUN OUT
OF THE OVEN,
OKAY WE'RE READY TO PULL THIS
SET HER DOWN,
LITTLE SPLASH,
BARBECUE, SLICE IT UP...
I GOTTA SEE THE INSIDE
OF THIS THING,
LOOK AT THAT.
THE PEPPERS AND THE ONIONS,
AND THE CHEESE MELTS PERFECTLY,
HMM, EXPLOSIVE!
IT REALLY IS,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I MAY HAVE TO GO HOME
AND SHAMPOO MY GOATEE.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR,
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S SO FULL OF
JUST EVERYTHING,
IT NEEDS A SPOON
AND A FORK...
A SPORK.
DIP IT IN THE BARBECUE...
YOU GET SO MUCH SAUCE
ON THAT PLATE,
YOU COULD PROBABLY
JUST EAT THE PLATE.
AND HE MAKES
HIS OWN BARBECUE SAUCE.
IT'S CAROLINA BASED...
I LOVE THE VINEGAR, HMM.
REAL NICE FLAVOR,
COMPLEMENTS IT WELL.
IT HAS A LITTLE BITE TO IT
AND IT'S VERY, VERY GOOD.
(Guy)
AND HE'S CRANKING OUT
5 GALLONS A DAY,
AND 1,500 POUNDS OF MEAT A WEEK.
ALL RIGHT GUYS,
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
BECAUSE FOLKS HAVE DISCOVERED
THE ORANGE TRAIN CAR.
IT'S A LITTLE
OUT OF THE WAY FOR US.
BUT GOOD BARBECUE
IS WORTH DRIVING FOR.
WHEN THEY FIRST OPENED,
THE LINES WERE OUT THE DOOR,
AND IT DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE LETTING UP AT ALL.
YOU MIGHT HAVE A SPOT
AT THE COUNTER, IF NOT...
YOU'RE EATIN' IN YOUR CAR.
COME IN TO TAKE OUT...
AND GET A NICE FULL PLATE
OF FOOD LIKE I LIKE TO EAT
WHEN I GO OUT.
THE SIDES ARE REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
THE POTATO SALAD
IS REAL CREAMY.
THE BEANS AND RICE,
THEY'RE REALLY FLAVORFUL.
YOU GET A MACARONI AND CHEESE
THAT'S LIKE NO OTHER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA ENGINEER ME
SOME KILLER MAC AND CHEESE?
COUPLE CUPS OF BUTTER,
GET THAT ALL MELTED UP
SO THAT YOU HAVE SOME SORT OF
A GOO TO THROW INTO THE POT.
GOO?
GOO.
AND WE JUST PUREE ONION,
A COUPLE CUPS OF GARLIC...
HEAR THAT LITTLE SIZZLE
THAT WENT IN THERE,
THAT'S JUST THE RIGHT THING.
THAT'S JUST THE RIGHT SIZZLE?
YEAH, FOUR EGGS,
KEEP IT ROLLIN',
KEEP IT ROLLIN.'
ALL RIGHT, GROUND OREGANO,
JUST START THROWING THESE IN,
YOU GOT THE PEPPER,
PAPRIKA AND SALT,
MILK, HEAVY CREAM
AND SOUR CREAM.
CRAZY!
NOW WE CAN START SLOWLY
WHISKING IN THE CHEESE,
FIRST IS CHEDDAR,
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
SOME FOREARMS
TO DO MAC AND CHEESE.
AND WHISK, AND WHISK,
AND WHISK,
OTHERWISE IT GETS ALL LUMPY
AND TURNS TO A BIG BLACK SPOT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE BOTTOM,
AND THAT'S UGLY.
ASIAGO, NOW WE GOT
A FOUR CHEESE BLEND
GOIN' IN,
FONTINA, ASIAGO,
PROVOLONE, PARMESAN.
I CAN ONLY WHIP SO FAST,
CAPTAIN.
I KNOW.
OKAY, SO OUR
CHEESE SAUCE IS DONE,
OUR NOODLES ARE READY,
LITTLE RIGATE, LITTLE EDGES,
SO THE SAUCE
WILL GRAB ONTO IT.
ABOUT A HANDFUL OF
ASIAGO AGAIN,
ON THE PASTA.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF THE CHEDDAR,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA POUR
THE CHEESE SAUCE
RIGHT IN ON IT?
I JUST TRY NOT TO SPILL THERE.
NOW, WE'RE GONNA POUR THIS
INTO THE PAN...PERFECT.
MORE OF THE ORANGE CHEESE.
MORE OF THE ORANGE CHEESE,
NOW WE PUT THE CRUST
ON THE TOP,
GOLDFISH...PRETTY SIMPLE.
I LOVE THIS...CLASSIC.
DO A QUICK WRAP
WITH CELLOPHANE AND FOIL,
AND IN THE OVEN IT GOES.
350?
RIGHT.
AND YOU SET THE TIMER?
YOU DON'T WANT TO FORGET...
35 MINUTES.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO, HUH?
LOOK AT THAT CHEESY...
HMM, WOW, JUST LOOK
HOW CHEESY THAT IS.
THE CHEESE OUTWEIGHS
THE PASTA.
THE CHUNKY NUGGETS
OF GOLDFISH ON TOP...
THAT'S A NICE MOVE
RIGHT THERE, THAT'S CHEESY.
I LOVE THE MAC AND CHEESE.
VERY TASTY, CREAMY,
IT'S JUST GOOD STUFF.
THEY DO A GREAT JOB
AT WHAT THEY DO,
AND THEIR FOOD SHOWS THAT.
(Jeff)
ALL RIGHT, THREE MEAT COMBO.
BEST BARBECUE AROUND...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT ELSE
TO SAY, GOOD IS GOOD.
THREE SANDWICHES UP...
THEY PUT THEIR HEART
INTO IT.
CHECK IT OUT,
PACIFICA, CALIFORNIA,
YOU'LL SEE IT,
A BIG ORANGE BOX CAR,
AND YOU CAN COME
GET SOME PORK RIBS.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
WHO'D FIGURE GOOD BARBECUE
IN CONNECTICUT?
BUT THAT'S WHERE
WE'RE HEADING...
PULLED PORK,
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
FOR A TASTE OF CAROLINA.
SMOKINESS, THE FLAVOR'S
ALWAYS THERE.
I WOULDN'T DO A THING
TO IT DIFFERENT.
THE THING ABOUT PEOPLE
AND BARBECUE IS THAT
IF THEY LOVE BARBECUE,
THEY REALLY LOVE IT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE A CLUB
OR A SPECIAL ORGANIZATION.
AND IT'S ALWAYS GREAT
TO RUN INTO ANOTHER MEMBER
AND HEAR WHAT THEY'RE DOIN'
WITH THEIR BARBECUE.
LIKE UP HERE
IN FAIRFIELD, CONNECTICUT,
AT WILSON'S HOLY SMOKE BARBECUE,
I HEAR IT'S ON POINT.
WHO'D FIGURE GOOD BARBECUE
IN CONNECTICUT?
PULLED PORK PLATTER.
ED WILSON, THAT'S WHO.
ROCK 'N ROLL.
A FORMER BACKYARD BARBECUER...
THAT'S 16 YEARS AGO.
WHO DECIDED TO GET SERIOUS
ABOUT DOIN' IT RIGHT.
THERE'S A PICTURE OF YOU
AND A BUDDY OF MINE,
MIKEY Z...
AT THE BRISKET COOKING SCHOOL.
I WAS AT THIS SCHOOL.
WHAT A SMALL WORLD,
WE WERE AT THE SAME
BARBECUE CAMP SEVEN YEARS AGO.
THAT WAS TEXAS,
BUT ED'S BEEN
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY...
FIGURING OUT WHAT KIND
OF BARBECUE HE LIKES BEST.
WILSON'S IS A REGIONAL
CELEBRATION OF BARBECUE STYLE.
WE HAVE A TEXAS-STYLE BRISKET...
THE BRISKET, I LOVE.
AND MY RIBS,
MEMPHIS-STYLE BABY BACKS.
THEY'RE LEAN,
THEY TASTE GREAT.
BABY BACK RIBS ARE EXCELLENT.
AND SO ARE THESE...
LOVE THE ST. LOUIS RIBS.
AND ALL KINDS OF SAUCE...
WE'VE GOT SOME CHIPOTLE.
WE HAVE THE EASTERN
NORTH CAROLINA STYLE...
AND IF YOU'RE TALKIN'
NORTH CAROLINA,
YOU'VE GOT TO BE TALKIN'
PULLED PORK.
PULLED PORK,
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
THE SMOKINESS,
THE FLAVOR'S ALWAYS THERE.
EXCELLENT.
SO A COUPLE OF PORK SHOULDERS,
BONE-IN THOUGH...
BONE-IN BOSTON BUTTS...
YOU'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH YOUR RUB.
YES SIR.
(Guy)
A MEMPHIS-STYLE DRY RUB...
EVERYTHING'S
FROM SCRATCH HERE.
WITH ED'S OWN TWIST.
CUMIN...
NICE KICKER THERE,
NOT HIS FIRST RODEO.
WE'RE GONNA DRY RUB THIS...
I DO THE SIDES FIRST.
THE MORE THE MERRIER,
YOU CAN'T HAVE ENOUGH FOR ME.
POP IN THE SMOKER
FOR ABOUT 16 TO 18 HOURS,
WHAT KIND OF INTERNAL
TEMPERATURE ARE YOU
TRYIN' TO PULL?
SOMEWHERE OVER 185,
SO IT WILL JUST FALL APART.
NICE!
IS IT READY?
IT'S READY.
YOU'RE PUTTIN' GLOVES ON.
DOCTOR.
THESE ARE BIG BOY
BARBECUES RIGHT HERE.
LOOK AT THOSE THINGS,
AND YOU GOTTA WATCH IT
'CAUSE I'M A BARK SHARK.
THIS BROWN, CRISPY COATING
ON THE OUTSIDE
IS CALLED THE BARK.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE PART HERE.
LOOK AT THIS,
SEE THE COLOR
THAT PUT ON THERE?
TALKIN' TO ME NOW!
PHENOMENAL, YOU WANT TO TRY IT?
SO EVERY TIME SOMEONE
ORDERS A SANDWICH,
THIS IS HOW IT'S GOIN' DOWN?
ABSOLUTELY.
BARK, LITTLE SLAW...
AND I WANT TO TRY
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAUCE.
LOOK AT THAT!
OH, THAT IS GOOD!
IT'S RIDICULOUSLY BIG...
THE BARBECUE SAUCE IS
NOT TOO HOT,
NOT TOO VINEGARY,
IT GETS ITS WAY
ALL AROUND THE PORK.
THE CRUNCH FROM THE SLAW,
A LITTLE BIT OF BARK,
I WOULDN'T DO
A THING TO IT DIFFERENT.
YEP, I'M GONNA HAVE TO GO
DOWN TO THE RENTAL PLACE
AND GET THAT
CARPET SHAMPOOER AGAIN.
I'M A PULLED PORK NUT,
AND THIS IS GREAT.
THE FLAVOR OF
THE PULLED PORK IS GREAT.
EVERYTHING THEY HAVE HERE
IS JUST REALLY GOOD.
WHETHER YOU'RE HAVING
THE RIBS OR THE GREAT SAUCES
THAT HE HAS HERE,
THAT ARE ALL HOMEMADE...
WE GOT SWEET TANG TOMATO BASE...
HOLY CHIPOTLE...
A LITTLE BIT SPICY
AND HAS A SMOKY FLAVOR TOO.
(Guy)
AND HE'S DOIN' A TANGY
CAROLINA SAUCE.
MY FAVORITE.
LET'S DO THIS...
CIDER VINEGAR,
SOME WATER NOW...
PUT THE MOONSHINE IN...
NICE AND SIMPLE,
WHAT YOU SEE
IS WHAT YOU GET.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
SOME SUGAR,
AND A LITTLE RED CHILI FLAKE.
SEE, YOU GOT MY FAVORITE THINGS,
YOU GOT THE VINEGAR,
YOU GOT THE HEAT,
AND KETCHUP.
SO LET THIS SIMMER?
BRING IT UP TO A SIMMER,
AND THEN WE'LL COOL IT DOWN
AND HOLD IT.
AND THEN WE'LL TASTE IT.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM, I CAN ALREADY SMELL IT...
OH GOD,
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
IF THEY MADE THAT BOAT
HUMAN SIZE, I'D GET IN IT.
IT'S GOT A SWEETNESS TO IT,
BUT ALSO THE TANGINESS
OF THE VINEGAR,
THAT JUST MELDS
REAL WELL TOGETHER.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH THE SOUTH
AND THIS TURNS OUT TO BE
THE BEST BARBECUE
THAT WE'VE RUN INTO.
WE'VE DONE EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH.
EVEN A DOZEN HOMEMADE SIDES.
MASHED SWEET POTATOES,
POTATO SALAD...
COLLARD GREENS, HUH?
THEY'RE MY FAVORITE.
BLACK-EYED PEA SALAD,
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
OH, ABSOLUTELY NOT.
LITTLE VINAIGRETTE,
SOME DIJON,
ONIONS, PEPPERS, PARSLEY,
A WHOLE GET-UP
ON SOME PARSLEY.
RED PEPPER, JALAPENO,
AND SOME GARLIC,
BLACK-EYED PEAS.
SLOWLY POUR THIS IN?
YES, SIR.
I LIKE IT,
NICE LITTLE SIDE DISH,
REALLY NICE.
EVERYTHING THE GUY MAKES
IS REALLY GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE
TO CALL YOUR TYPE OF BARBECUE?
I TRY TO DO
A COMPETITION-QUALITY
BARBECUE.
(Guy)
CLASSIC BARBECUE RECIPES
ED PICKED UP ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
PULLED CHICKEN SANDWICH...
AND SOME OF HIS OWN,
LIKE THIS ONE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A BRINE
FOR MY CHICKEN.
OKAY.
TWO GALLONS OF WATER...
CHICKEN TAKES TO BRINE
SO WELL,
IT'S THE OSMOSIS, YOU KNOW,
IT'S TRANSFERRING IN SOME
OF THAT FLAVOR.
KOSHER SALT, SOME SUGAR,
ONION AND GARLIC,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE PICKLING SPICE,
I DIDN'T THINK ABOUT
THE OLD BAY IDEA,
BUT I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE
ROLLIN' WITH THAT.
SO LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT,
YOU'RE GONNA LET THIS SIT HERE
AND SIMMER A LITTLE BIT,
THEN COOL IT DOWN,
HIT IT WITH SOME ICE,
KIND OF DILUTING IT...
SUBMERGE THE CHICKENS,
THEY'LL SIT OVERNIGHT.
AND NOW I'M GONNA RUB 'EM
AND PREPARE 'EM FOR SMOKING.
SAME DRY RUB FOR THE CHICKEN
AND THE PORK AND THE BEEF?
YEP.
TUCK 'EM UP UNDERNEATH
SO THE WING TIPS
DON'T BURN OFF.
HIT SOME IN THE CAVITY.
HIT THE BACK.
WE'RE GONNA GET THESE DOWN,
GO FOR SIX HOURS AND THEN...
BIRDS ARE READY.
OH, OH...
IT'S LIKE A WATERFALL
IN MY MOUTH AS I'M DROOLING.
LOOK AT THAT...OH!
THERE AIN'T NO JOKIN',
THAT BIRD IS SMOKIN'.
THE RUB'S NOT OVERPOWERING,
YOU REALLY GET TO ENJOY
THE SMOKE,
THE BIRD IS MONSTER-TENDER,
FANTASTIC BALANCE OF FLAVORS,
YOU GOT YOUR PhD
IN DELICIOUS, DUDE.
APPRECIATE THAT.
PERFECT, ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
MAKE A NOISE
A CHICKEN MAKES.
(chicken noise)
REALLY?
BEST BARBECUE I'VE HAD.
IT'S JUICY AND IT'S GOT
SOME NICE SMOKED FLAVOR.
CONNECTICUT AND BARBECUE
DON'T GO HAND IN HAND.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE,
BUT IT'S HERE AND IT'S GOOD.
ED WILSON MAKES IT GOOD,
THE LOVE HE PUTS IN,
EVERYTHING COMES OUT PERFECT.
REMEMBER, BARBECUE'S
A YEAR-ROUND SPORT.
CELEBRATE IT, MAN.
THANKS, WHAT A GUY, HUH?
(Guy)
NEXT STOP...TEXAS.
RACK-O-RIBS.
THE RIBS ARE REALLY TASTY.
WHERE THIS GUY SAYS
THE SECRET'S IN THE WOOD.
FOR ME GREEN MESQUITE
HAD THE BEST FLAVOR,
THE MOST CONSISTENT FLAVOR.
THAT'S GOOD.
ON "TRIPLE D,"
WHEN YOU'RE IN JERSEY,
WELL, YOU HEAD INTO A DINER.
YOU'RE IN NEW ENGLAND,
IT'S A CLAM SHACK.
WHEN YOU'RE IN TEXAS,
AND YOU'RE LOOKIN' FOR
A LOCAL FAVORITE,
CHANCES ARE,
IT'S A BARBECUE JOINT,
LIKE GREEN MESQUITE,
HERE IN AUSTIN.
THE BEST BARBECUE IN TOWN.
TWO CHOPPED BEEFS
COMIN' UP.
ALL SET FOR NOW?
THANK YOU.
IS IT YUMMY?
TASTY... A LITTLE MESSY...
I MEAN, IT'S AMAZING.
SMOKY FLAVOR.
THEY USED
A GREEN MESQUITE WOOD...
(Guy)
WHICH MOST FOLKS WILL TELL YA,
WILL SMOKE UP THE JOINT.
ARE YOU BREATHING
IN THE MIDDLE OF THIS?
BARELY.
AND CLOG YOUR SMOKER.
YOU HAVE TO REPLACE FLUES
EVERY YEAR.
OH, 'CAUSE IT MUST
JUST LEAVE SOME SAP.
IT EATS IT UP.
BUT IT'S ALSO
THE ONLY KIND OF WOOD
TOM DAVIS WILL USE.
FOR ME, GREEN MESQUITE
HAD THE BEST FLAVOR,
THE MOST CONSISTENT FLAVOR,
AND AS LONG AS IT WAS
LESS THAN A YEAR OLD
AFTER IT WAS CUT,
IT'S CONSIDERED GREEN.
SO DOES THAT GIVE IT
A LITTLE SNAPPIER,
LITTLE PEPPIER BITE TO IT?
IT'S BAD ON PITS,
BUT GREAT ON MEAT.
IT HAS A GOOD,
BOLD TASTE TO IT.
IT GIVES A REALLY NICE
MESQUITE FLAVOR...
ON EVERYTHING
HE'S CRANKING OUT.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY!
FROM BRISKET AND CHOPPED BEEF
TO PORK RIBS.
HERE IN BEEF COUNTRY.
I PREFER TO DO THINGS
I LIKE TO EAT.
THE RIBS ARE AWESOME,
FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
HOW MANY RACKS
ARE YOU DOIN' IN A DAY?
PROBABLY 20 RACKS A DAY.
OKAY.
THIS IS CONSIDERED A SPARE RIB,
NOT AS A ST. LOUIS?
NO, A ST. LOUIS
IS A SPECIAL CUT.
IT'S CALLED A 3 1/2
AND DOWN.
3 1/2 POUNDS
AND DOWN IS THE SIZE,
THAT'S THE WAY
THAT THEY'RE ALL PACKED.
THESE DO HAVE THE CHINE BONE
STILL ON IT,
THE FAT LOOKS LIKE IT'S
BEEN TRIMMED OFF THIS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
THE RUB DOWN...
GET IT, GIVE ME THE RUN DOWN,
GIVE ME THE RUB DOWN?
HERE WE GO...
WE GOT BROWN SUGAR,
ONION POWDER,
WE GOT YOUR GARLIC POWDER...
KIND OF THE USUAL SUSPECTS
TO MAKING RUB.
THAT'S RIGHT.
PAPRIKA, CAYENNE,
WHICH I KNOW YOU LOVE.
YOU RUB IT IN REALLY GOOD,
YOU DON'T FOOL AROUND,
IF YOU GOT IT,
USE IT.
LOOK AT THAT,
GREAT COLOR ON IT,
THAT'LL MAKE A NICE BARK.
NOW, HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA GO ON FOR?
4 1/2 TO 5 HOURS.
THAT'S A NICE LONG TIME.
TEMPERATURE'S ABOUT 195
TO 200, RACK-O-RIBS.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR 'EM.
YOU GOTTA BE CAREFUL ON THAT,
THEY DON'T FALL APART.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OOH THE COLOR,
THIS IS WITH GREEN MESQUITE.
GREEN MESQUITE ONLY,
I LOVE 'EM.
THIS IS GONNA BE
A NEW ONE FOR ME.
OKAY, YOU WANT TO
GIVE ME YOURS?
SHARE AND SHARE NOT ALIKE.
YOU BE CHER,
I'LL BE SONNY.
ALL RIGHT,
SO CUT THESE AND EAT 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT,
THEY'RE JUST DRIPPING
RIGHT OUT OF THERE.
BOY, THEY'RE JUICY.
THAT'S GOOD,
I LIKE THE SMOKE RING.
I LIKE THAT BROWN SUGAR
OUT THERE,
THIS IS THE BARBECUE SAUCE?
NOW, HOW DO YOU DO IT?
ON TOP OF THE RIBS PLEASE,
MY MOTHER MIGHT BE WATCHING.
HMM...HMM,
YOU MAKE THE SAUCE TOO?
YES.
HIS TAKE ON KANSAS CITY STYLE,
35 GALLONS A WEEK.
WHAT...
WE'RE IN BARBECUE COUNTRY.
I THINK BARBECUE SAUCE
ON A NAPKIN WOULD BE GOOD TOO.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT IT
IS THE REALLY SUBTLE FLAVOR,
YOU CAN TASTE THE PORK.
GREEN MESQUITE,
I'VE SEEN IT ALL.
THE RIBS ARE REALLY TASTY.
SOME OF THE BEST BARBECUE
I'VE HAD IN AUSTIN.
DO YOU PULL PORK TOO?
I LOVE PULLED PORK.
AND YOU'RE NOT ASKED
TO LEAVE THE STATE OF TEXAS
IF YOU'RE EATIN' PORK?
TEXAS IS A BIG-TIME BEEF
COUNTRY, SO A LOT OF PLACES
DON'T CARRY PORK.
BUT REMEMBER,
THIS GUY'S DOIN' WHAT
HE LIKES TO EAT.
JAMBALAYA, JAMBALAYA!
WITH SMOKED TURKEY,
CHICKEN AND SAUSAGE.
THIS IS TEXAS JAMBALAYA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THIS IS TOM'S KIND OF TACO.
TACOS?
YEAH, THEY DO IT IN TACOS.
WE DECIDED, "WHY DON'T WE
JUST MIX UP SOME BRISKET,
"AND THROW SOME LETTUCE
AND TOMATO AND CHEESE ON IT,
"AND WE'LL CALL IT A TACO."
THE BUBBA TACOS
ARE MY FAVORITE.
THE BUBBA, BUBBA?
THAT'S SMOKED BARBECUE,
BUT IT'S COVERED UP
WITH LETTUCE AND TOMATO
AND SALSA.
THE LAST TIME I HAD
THE PULLED PORK TACOS,
THEY WERE REALLY GOOD.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
A BARBECUE JOINT.
IT'S A "WHAT TOM
LIKES TO EAT" JOINT.
AND THAT MEANS WINGS.
THE WINGS ARE NICE AND JUICY.
OKAY, NOW TELL ME
ABOUT WINGS.
MARGARINE FIRST, OKAY?
JUST THROW IT OVER HERE
AND LET IT MELT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE MARGARINE OF MELTISH...
THE BROWN SUGAR NEXT,
CHILI SAUCE AFTER THAT...
I'M GONNA JUST STAND BACK HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT!
'CAUSE THE WAY YOU'RE
WHISKIN' AND WHIPPIN'...
NOW SOME REGULAR HOT SAUCE?
LOUISIANA HOT SAUCE RIGHT HERE.
NOW, WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE WING SAUCE...
ALL OVER THE WINGS.
BUT THEY'RE NOT COOKED.
IF YOU DEEP FRY THE WINGS
WITH THAT SAUCE ON THEM,
IT'S GONNA BURN THE SAUCE.
THAT'S RIGHT,
SO WHAT YOU DO
IS YOU SMOKE IT FIRST,
FOR APPROXIMATELY ONE HOUR
AT 200 DEGREES.
REALLY?
HERE WE GO ON THE PIT,
YOU ALMOST GET USED TO THIS.
I WOULD JUST RUN
AND THROW IT AT IT.
I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
NOW THEY'RE OUT OF THE SMOKER,
NOW THEY GO IN THE FRYER.
FOR A MINUTE AND A HALF...
THIS IS JUST GONNA BE
TO CRISP.
THERE WE GO,
NICE AND A LITTLE DARK THERE.
NOW, I PUT IT IN A BOWL,
TAKE MY WING SAUCE
AND KIND OF POUR IT LIKE THAT,
KIND OF SHAKE 'EM AROUND.
YOU SCARE ME WITH THAT
WINGIN' AND SAUCIN'...
THERE THEY ARE!
THE WING IS NICE AND TENDER,
A LOT OF GREAT MOISTURE TO IT,
NOT TOO SPICY.
NOT DEADLY.
I'M GLAD THIS IS NOT TOO SMOKY.
IT HAS A LITTLE BIT,
BUT NOT MUCH.
YOU CAN BARELY TASTE IT.
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD WING!
THESE ONES DEFINITELY
ARE MORE TENDER
AND MUCH MORE JUICY.
IT'S A SWEET SAUCE,
NOT TOO SPICY.
I'M INTERESTED IN TRYING ONE,
BUT I FIGURE I'D JUST
GET A BIG...
MAN, THOSE ARE GREAT!
THIS IS MY WIFE, LORI.
PRETTY CRISPY,
JUST HOW I LIKE IT.
IT'S THE BEST, SO...
I LIKE THE FRIED OKRA.
I THOUGHT I WAS JUST COMING
TO JUST A BARBECUE JOINT,
BUT IT'S NOT.
THEY CAN GET BARBECUE
AND I CAN GET WHAT I WANT TOO.
(Guy)
'CAUSE HEY, THIS IS TEXAS.
I LOVE CHICKEN FRIED STEAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
I'VE NEVER HAD THE GUEST
OF THIS SHOW OUT-EAT ME.
OH HEAVEN!
(Guy)
AT GREEN MESQUITE BARBECUE,
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
OWNER TOM DAVIS HAS BEEN
MAKING HIS FAVORITES SINCE '88.
THEIR BARBECUE IS
THE BEST IN TOWN.
(Guy)
FROM BRISKET AND RIBS...
THE RIBS ARE REALLY TASTY.
TO SCRATCH-MADE JAMBALAYA...
THIS IS TEXAS JAMBALAYA.
ALL KINDS OF SANDWICHES...
CATFISH PO BOY!
AND EVEN THIS TEXAS FAVORITE...
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK.
BIG HERE?
VERY BIG HERE.
START OUT WITH EGGS,
AND HOW LONG YOU GUYS
BEEN MAKIN' THIS?
UH, 20 YEARS.
REALLY?
ALL RIGHT, MILK,
WHOLE MILK ONLY, PLEASE.
OKAY SO THIS IS IT.
EGGS ARE WHISKED,
SO WE GOT YOUR
SELF-RISING FLOUR,
SEASONED PEPPER...
SO IT'S SALT,
SUGAR, PEPPER,
AND THEN RED, YELLOW
AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS
THAT ARE DRIED.
IT'S A SWEET, BLACK PEPPER,
IS WHAT I CALL IT.
I LOVE THIS BELL PEPPER
THING IN HERE,
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
IT ADDS A LITTLE BIT TO IT...
RANCH DRY DRESSING MIX,
ONCE YOU GET THAT ALL
NICE AND MIXED UP...
WOW, THAT'S A LOT
OF SEASONING!
OKAY, DO YOU GO FLOUR...
I GO MILK...
SO YOU DON'T PUT
THE FLOUR ON FIRST.
I COME FROM THE SCHOOL
IF YOU PUT THE FLOUR
ON IT FIRST,
IT HELPS THE EGG WASH
STICK TO THE FLOUR.
EVERYBODY SAYS THAT.
YEAH, WHO CARES ABOUT
THOSE CULINARY PROCEDURES
AND PROCESSES?
I GET YELLED AT,
EVERY TIME I DO IT,
I PROBABLY DO IT BACKWARDS.
WE DOUBLE DIP ALL OUR
CHICKEN FRIED STEAKS...
SO THAT'S GOT TO HAVE
A THICK BATTER ON IT.
OH, SO SORRY,
SO SORRY.
YOU KNOW WHAT,
HE'S DEFINITELY SOMETHING!
THIS IN HERE...
THROW ANOTHER BASKET ON TOP?
YES, 'CAUSE IT WILL FLOAT...
FOR ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
SHE'S READY...
SHAKE, SHAKE, SHAKE...
I'M GONNA GET AWAY,
YOU'RE GONNA SHAKE, SHAKE,
SHAKE ME INTO E. R.
VERY HOT.
THAT CLOSE TO MY TOES.
AND SMEAR ALL KINDS OF
GRAVY ON IT.
YOU CAN GUT IT WITH A FORK,
SO YOU GOT TO KNOW YOU
GOT SOME TENDER FACTOR THERE.
HMM, I LIKE IT,
THEN YOU GOTTA PICK UP
THAT RANCH DRESSING
IN THERE A LITTLE BIT,
THAT'S PROBABLY THE CRUNCHIEST,
OR THE BIGGEST BATTER I'VE FOUND
ON ONE.
I LOVE IT, I LOVE IT.
IT'S HALF GONE!
I'LL BE OVER HERE.
I'VE BEEN KNOWN TO TAKE
WINGS OUT OF PEOPLE'S HANDS.
OH HEAVEN!
THAT IS SOME THICK BATTER
ON THAT, HUH?
YEAH, IT'S VERY GOOD.
DEFINITELY EXCELLENT,
EXCELLENT FOOD.
IT'S AN AWESOME PLACE.
IT'S BARBECUE,
AND I LOVE BARBECUE.
LOVE THE GREEN MESQUITE.
GREAT SERVICE, GREAT FOOD.
THERE'S ONE THING THAT
I THINK WE'RE PRETTY SURE ON.
UH-OH.
YOU HAVE A LOVE AFFAIR
WITH FOOD, MAN,
I LOVE IT.
YOU LOVE COMIN' TO WORK.
I LOVE COMIN' TO WORK.
THIS IS NOT EVEN WORK,
IS IT?
NO, IT'S JUST FUN, IT'S HOME.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE D...
"DINER'S, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
ON TELEVISION BEFORE?
DANCING ONLY.
I USED TO DO THIS
ALL THE TIME...
AND THE BOOGALOO.
AND YOU THOUGHT IT WAS JUST
GOOD BRISKET AND WINGS!