HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOO!
WHO SENT ME THE E-MAIL?
PLACES YOU SENT ME,
IN NEW ORLEANS...
IT IS JUST A BLAST.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
IT DOESN'T GET MUCH MORE
NEW ORLEANS THAN THIS.
WHERE A LOT OF YOU SWEAR
THIS JOINT MAKES...
THE BEST PO' BOY
I'VE EVER HAD.
THIS IS THE BEST.
NOT ONE OF THE BEST...
NO, THIS IS THE BEST.
THAT'S LEGIT
RIGHT THERE.
AND THE COLD CUTS
COME OUT HOT.
IT ALL COMES TOGETHER.
WOW.
IN SALT LAKE CITY...
THIS TASTES LIKE, MMM,
A LITTLE PIECE OF HEAVEN.
AT A LANDMARK THAT'S
NEARLY 80 YEARS OLD.
MY AUNT HAD BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 30-SOMETHING YEARS,
AND I'M KEEPING
THE TRADITION GOING.
ONE BISCUIT AT A TIME,
AND THEY'VE MADE SO MANY...
CLOSE TO THREE MILLION.
THEY CAN DO IT
BLINDFOLDED.
HE'S GOT THE MARGARINE.
HE'S PICKING UP SPEED.
WATER?
HE KNOWS WHERE
HIS BINS ARE.
"BISCUIT BAKING BAD BOY."
YEAH.
AND IN CENTRAL CONNECTICUT...
IT'S JUST FABULOUS.
YOU WALK AWAY WITH ONE
DELICIOUS MEAL AFTER ANOTHER.
A CLASSIC DINER...
VERY INTERESTING
COMBINATIONS.
MAKING HASH
OUT OF ANYTHING.
BRISKET HASH,
WILD TURKEY HASH.
CLAM HASH.
DUCK HASH.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
WITHOUT QUESTION,
THE DUCK'S MY FAVORITE PART.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON TRIPLE "D," WE LOVE TO GO
TO THE PLACES YOU SEND US,
AND THIS TIME IT'S NEW ORLEANS--
NICE JOB, BY THE WAY--
TO WHERE FOLKS ARE GOING NUTS
FOR A LOCAL SANDWICH
CALLED A PO' BOY.
SO THE NEXT TIME
YOU'RE ON A PO' BOY PATROL
AND YOU'RE IN NEW ORLEANS,
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT PARASOL'S.
ROAST BEEF PO' BOY.
THE BEST PO' BOY
I'VE EVER HAD.
GREAT BEEF, GREAT BUN.
MADE WITH
TENDER LOVING CARE.
WHEN IT'S DRIPPING DOWN
YOUR ARMS, YOU KNOW IT'S GOOD.
BEST IN THE CITY.
A PO' BOY
MEANS A SANDWICH.
YOU GOT SHRIMP PO' BOY
AND OYSTER PO' BOY
AND HAM PO' BOY.
THE ROAST BEEF
IS THE BEST.
AND IT'S THE ONE THAT MADE
PARASOL'S A LOCAL LEGEND.
THIS IS THE BEST.
NOT ONE OF THE BEST.
NO, THIS IS THE BEST.
THIS IS THE BEST.
YES, ABSOLUTELY.
BY THE WAY, THIS IS ROSS,
WHO SENT US AN E-MAIL
AND SAID I GOTTA COME HERE.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
THIS JUST MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
JEFF PUTS A LITTLE
T.L.C. IN HIS PO' BOYS.
YES, HE DOES.
THAT WOULD BE JEFF CARRERAS...
ROAST BEEF.
WHO BOUGHT THIS JOINT
TEN YEARS AGO...
OYSTER.
AND KEPT THINGS THE WAY
THEY'VE ALWAYS BEEN,
ESPECIALLY THE ROAST BEEF.
THIS IS WHAT WAS
TAUGHT TO YOU?
YEAH, THIS WAS HANDED DOWN
FROM THE PASTEUR FAMILY
WHICH OWNED PARASOL'S.
TAKE AN INSIDE ROUND,
GET IT NICE AND LEAN,
IT'LL BE BOILED.
BOILED, NOT ROASTED.
NOT ROASTED.
I DON'T KNOW, MAN,
THAT SCARES ME.
YOU LET ME KNOW.
TO THE HOT TUB.
JUST WATER, NO SEASONING?
STRAIGHT WATER,
NO SEASONING.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
SEASONING
COMES AFTERWARDS.
OKAY. NOW HOW LONG
DO THESE GO DOWN FOR?
ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
WE'RE GOING
COMPLETELY COOKED.
WE'RE NOT LOOKING
FOR ANY MEDIUM RARE IN HERE.
NO MEDIUM RARE HERE, DUDE.
IT'S JUST BOILED BEEF.
I'M WAITING--
I'M EXPECTING SOMETHING BIG.
I MEAN, THEY E-MAIL ME AND SAY,
"YOU GOTTA GO TO PARASOL'S,
YOU GOTTA GO TO PARASOL'S."
WE'LL GET YOUR TASTE BUDS
DANCIN' HERE IN A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
LET IT COOL A LITTLE BIT,
THEN WE'LL SLICE IT UP,
THROW SOME GRAVY ON IT,
AND READY TO BE SERVED.
OUR HOT CAULDRON.
FROM THAT STOCK IS WHAT WE
MIX TOGETHER WITH SEASONINGS
TO MAKE THE GRAVY--
SOME FLOUR, SOME OIL,
BLACK PEPPER, GARLIC POWDER,
A LITTLE SALT.
WHAT WAS THAT--2 CUPS,
3 CUPS OF GARLIC POWDER?
UH, PRETTY MUCH ABOUT
A 1-POUNDER.
HOW MUCH GRAVY
IS THIS GONNA MAKE?
4 GALLONS OF GRAVY.
WOW.
A LITTLE KITCHEN BOUQUET
FOR COLOR.
AND YOU MAKE THIS
HOW MANY TIMES A WEEK?
EVERY DAY.
YOU MAKE THIS EVERY DAY?
THIS IS GONNA GO INTO
THE BOILING CAULDRON?
YEP.
I'M TRYING NOT
TO GET ANY ON YOU, MAN.
NOTHIN' BUT BROWN GRAVY.
TASTE THIS.
WOW. I WOULDN'T KICK
THAT OUT OF A SANDWICH.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT.
YOU COULD SERVE THAT ON MY
FLIP-FLOPS, IT WOULD TASTE GOOD.
IT'S NICE AND EASIER TO SLICE
ONCE IT'S COLD, YOU KNOW?
IT'S LIKE
BEEF JERKY, DUDE.
DRY, NO FLAVOR.
FOR NOW.
FROM THERE, WE'RE JUST
PUTTING GRAVY ON IT,
STICK IT INTO THE OVEN
ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO, IF THAT.
DUDE, YOU BETTER
BE DELIVERIN'.
ROAST BEEF IS DONE.
FINAL OUTCOME OF IT.
NOW YOU'RE GOING TO SHOW ME
THE ROAST BEEF PO' BOY
THAT YOU'VE WON ALL THESE
AWARDS FOR. WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
LOOK AT THAT THING.
CUT THE BREAD IN HALF.
OKAY, NOW WE TOAST THIS?
NOT YET.
WE TOAST THE BREAD
THOUGH, RIGHT?
WE DO TOAST THE BREAD.
YOU LIKE TO TOAST THE BREAD
AFTER YOU PUT EVERYTHING ON IT?
YES.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
THAT'S FOR ONE SIDE.
SURE, LOCK IT OUT, MAN.
AND THIS IS HOW
YOU MAKE IT?
THAT IS PRETTY MUCH
THE ROAST BEEF PO' BOY.
STICK IT IN THE OVEN,
LET IT TOAST THE BREAD
NICE AND TOASTY
FOR A COUPLE MINUTES.
MR. "I JUST PUT LETTUCE
IN THE OVEN."
WHAT'S THAT ALL ABOUT?
TOAST THE BREAD AHEAD OF TIME.
NO, THAT'S NOT THE WAY
WE DO THINGS AROUND HERE.
EVIDENTLY.
DIG INTO THAT.
MMM.
OH, MY GOD. THAT ROAST BEEF
IS CAPITAL "T" TENDER, MAN.
OH, YEAH, IT JUST FALLS APART.
AS DRY AS IT WAS EARLIER...
FROM AS DRY AS IT WAS--
JUICY, MESSY, CREAMY.
THAT'S LEGIT RIGHT THERE.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
DUDE, THAT'S GREAT.
WHEN I SAW THAT ROAST BEEF,
I'M LIKE, "THERE'S NO WAY
THAT GRAVY'S GONNA SAVE THIS."
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
BEST ROAST BEEF GRAVY
YOU'VE EVER HAD IN YOUR LIFE.
IT'S VERY JUICY.
NICE AND SLOPPY.
THIS THING'S A LITTLE MESSY,
BUT IT GOES DOWN EASY.
BEST ROAST BEEF PO' BOY
IN THE CITY.
UNCHANGED FOREVER,
JUST LIKE THE PLACE.
BEST VIBE IN THE WORLD.
(man) IT'S A PLACE THAT REALLY
JUST MAKES YOU FEEL COMFORTABLE.
ALWAYS JUST A TON OF PEOPLE,
PEOPLE YOU KNOW.
TYPICAL NEW ORLEANS.
WHERE TRADITION MATTERS...
(man) THE BUILDING
ITSELF IS LIKE 1898...
AND FOLKS ARE GETTIN'
WHAT THEY LOVE.
(Guy) HOW'S THE GUMBO?
IT'S AWESOME.
I DON'T CARE FOR
THICK GUMBOS.
WOW.
THAT'S TASTY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I COULD GET BUSY
ON THIS.
VERY SPICY.
NOT FOR THE FAINT OF HEART.
AND ANOTHER LOCAL FAVORITE...
BOUDIN BALLS.
A PORK RICE AND HERB SAUSAGE
ROLLED UP AND DEEP-FRIED.
VERY SPICY.
A COUPLE BOUDIN BALLS
WITH SOME GUINNESS--
CAN'T BEAT IT.
I'M HAVING A MUFFULETTA,
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
ANOTHER NEW ORLEANS
CLASSIC...
WOW, THIS IS GONNA BE
A HONKER, HUH?
DONE THE PARASOL'S WAY.
GOTTA GRILL ALL THE MEATS--
PROSCIUTTO.
YOU GRILL THE PROSCIUTTO?
YEAH.
I THINK IT'S ILLEGAL IN ITALY
TO COOK THE PROSCIUTTO.
OH, NO DOUBT THERE.
I GOT A LOT OF ITALIANS PROBABLY
SCREAMING AT ME RIGHT NOW.
A LITTLE HAM.
PLUS A LOAD OF SALAMI.
HOW MANY POUNDS ARE WE
TALKIN' HERE, GOOSE?
VERY MEATY SANDWICH.
BUTTER ON THE BUN.
WE'RE PROBABLY ONE OF THE ONLY
RESTAURANTS HERE IN TOWN
THAT DO IT WARM.
THE WAYS I'VE HAD IT
HAVE BEEN COLD.
PROSCIUTTO ON THE BOTTOM.
WE'RE AT THE POINT NOW
WHERE IT'S JUST NOT EVEN
FUNNY ANYMORE.
AND THE OLIVE SALAD.
A LITTLE CARROT,
A LITTLE CAULIFLOWER,
SOME GREEN OLIVES,
SOME BLACK OLIVES...
RED BELL PEPPER
IN A VINAIGRETTE.
OLIVE SALAD'S
MY FAVORITE PART OF THIS.
NICE, BIG, BEEFY SANDWICH.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS TO IT?
THROW IT IN THE OVEN
A COUPLE, THREE MINUTES,
TOAST UP THE TOP OF THE BREAD,
NICE AND TOASTY.
I CAN SMELL THE OLIVES.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
MMM.
TO DIE FOR?
WOW. I'VE HAD
A LOT OF 'EM COLD,
BUT WARM, YOU ALWAYS
BRING OUT OTHER FLAVORS.
JUST ADDS IT ALL TO IT.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
YES, INDEED.
EXCELLENT.
THANK YOU.
MAN, I'M DONE.
YOU'RE LIKE A HEAVY HITTER.
YOU'RE A DESIGNATED
FLAVOR HITTER.
IF YOU HAVEN'T HAD A MUFFULETTA,
YOU GOTTA COME TO PARASOL'S
AND TRY THIS.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT IT'S
ALL HOT. IT'S ALL FRESH.
REAL GOOD.
IT'S ALMOST AS BIG
AS YOU.
YEAH.
IT ALL COMES TOGETHER.
THEY VOUCH FOR EVERY
ITEM ON THE MENU.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE REALLY,
REALLY FANCY TO BE REALLY GOOD.
IT IS JUST A BLAST.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
IT DOESN'T GET MUCH MORE
NEW ORLEANS THAN THIS.
IT KIND OF LOOKS LIKE
A DIVE BAR OUT THERE.
IT IS.
OH, IT IS?
OKAY, GOOD, I DIDN'T...
WELL, I'M NOT A DINER,
I'M NOT A DRIVE-IN,
SO WHERE DOES THAT LEAVE ME?
WELL, NO, SEE?
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
MEANS, IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
IT'S FUNKY.
IF IT'S SOMETHING UNIQUE,
WE'LL GO TO IT.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HERE.
UP NEXT...
MMM. A LITTLE
PIECE OF HEAVEN.
WE'RE HEADING
TO SALT LAKE CITY...
TASTES BETTER THAN MY MOM
USED TO MAKE. SHH.
'CAUSE YOU WROTE AND TOLD ME
TO CHECK OUT THE BISCUITS.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY--
HEY, SIGN ME UP.
HMM. NICE JOB, MAN.
EXCELLENT.
YOU KNOW, WE FIND A LOT OF GREAT
PLACES HERE ON TRIPLE "D"
'CAUSE ONE PERSON E-MAILED US
AND TOLD US TO CHECK IT OUT,
OR MAYBE
TWO OR THREE PEOPLE.
AND THEN YOU GET
A PLACE LIKE THIS
RIGHT OUTSIDE
OF SALT LAKE CITY,
A 79-YEAR-OLD DINER
CALLED RUTH'S.
NOW THIS IS SUCH
A LOCAL LEGEND,
IT SEEMS LIKE WE HEARD
FROM EVERYBODY.
WHO SENT ME THE E-MAIL
ABOUT COMING TO RUTH'S?
ALL OF YOU HIT "SEND"
AT THE SAME TIME?
YES.
WHO WAS FIRST?
WHY'D YOU SEND ME
THE E-MAIL?
'CAUSE IT'S
A FABULOUS PLACE.
WHERE ARE YOU GONNA FIND
THIS KIND OF HISTORY?
WITH ALL KINDS
OF DINER CLASSICS.
I HAVE MEATLOAF.
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK.
I MOVED OUT HERE
TO GO TO COLLEGE IN '95.
BISCUITS WERE GOOD THEN.
THEY'RE JUST AS GOOD TODAY.
JUST LIKE THE PLACE ITSELF--
A LOCAL FAVORITE SINCE 1930.
READY TO PLATE IT.
AND OWNERS
ERIK AND TRACY NELSON
ARE MAKING SURE THAT WHEN
FOLKS COME TO RUTH'S...
CAN I GET YOUR NAME?
THEY GET WHAT THEY EXPECT.
MAC AND CHEESE.
CHEESY--IT'S GOOD.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WITH
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK.
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST.
BISCUIT, GRAVY!
BISCUITS AND GRAVY--
HEY, SIGN ME UP.
TASTES BETTER THAN MY MOM
USED TO MAKE. SHH.
THEY MAKE 'EM EVERY DAY.
ACTUALLY JUST ONE GUY--
BAKER INES MONREAL
CRANKIN' OUT
THOUSANDS A WEEK.
HOW MANY YEARS
HAVE YOU WORKED HERE?
ABOUT 16.
16 YEARS. YOU'VE ONLY MADE
CLOSE TO 3 MILLION BISCUITS.
THE "BISCUIT BAKING BAD BOY."
THERE WE GO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THAT NAME?
ALL RIGHT, SO HOW
DO WE MAKE A BISCUIT?
WE START WITH
MARGARINE FIRST.
WE'VE GOT SOME FLOUR
FROM HERE.
WRONG DAY TO WEAR BLACK.
BAKING POWDER--
ABOUT THAT MUCH.
"ABOUT THAT MUCH"?
THIS MUCH.
AND ABOUT THAT MUCH, JUST 'CAUSE
YOU'VE MADE THREE MILLION--
THREE MILLION BISCUITS--
WELL, YOU KNOW--
I CAN MEASURE BY HAND.
SALT, SUGAR.
EGGS.
THAT'S A LOT OF EGGS.
(whistles)
BUTTERMILK, WATER.
TURN IT SLOW.
THEN YOU STOP IT.
THAT'S IT?
NO, WE CAN ADD
MORE WATER.
OKAY, YOU JUST KINDA
DO IT BY FEEL.
SO LET ME ASK YOU THIS--
DO YOU THINK
I COULD BLINDFOLD YOU
AND YOU COULD MAKE THIS?
YES.
WE GOTTA DO THIS.
THERE YOU GO.
READY.
OKAY, GET STARTED.
HE'S GOT THE MARGARINE.
HE KNOWS WHERE HIS BINS ARE.
IT'S NOT BAD.
HE'S ADDING THE SALT!
(speaking indistinctly)
HE'S PICKING UP
SPEED AS HE GOES!
NOW FOR THE EGGS.
THERE WE GO.
BUTTERMILK, BUTTER.
THIS IS AMAZING.
THEN WE'LL JUST
LET IT MIX.
AMAZING.
YOU ARE THE BLINDFOLDED
BISCUIT BAKING BAD BOY
RIGHT HERE.
YEAH.
THERE WILL BE MORE
FLOUR ON TOP.
SO YOU CAN WORK WITH IT.
GET YOUR BISCUIT CUTTER.
OH, WE'RE DOING IT NOW.
IT'S OKAY.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
YOU DO EACH ONE
OF 'EM LIKE THIS?
JUST LIKE THAT.
HE'S LIKE A MACHINE.
THERE'S GOTTA BE
A SECRET BUTTON
SO THESE GO
IN THE OVEN NOW?
THESE GO IN THE OVEN
RIGHT NOW.
300 DEGREES,
35, 40 MINUTES...
YES.
TILL THEY GET A NICE
BROWN ON TOP.
WE CAN MAKE SOME GRAVY.
WE START WITH THE OIL,
DICED ONIONS,
GARLIC, PORK SAUSAGE,
SO WE GOT IT
COOKED DOWN.
LIKE THAT'S NOT GONNA
BE GREAT GRAVY.
WE HAVE THE BLACK PEPPER,
SALT, DRY BASIL,
AND THEN WE JUST SAUTé
'EM A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN A LITTLE FLOUR
TO MAKE THE ROUX.
HEAVY CREAM AND MILK.
LET IT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER FOR A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE,
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
THERE'S YOUR
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
WOW.
IT'S LIKE MOUND O' BISCUIT.
MMM.
THAT'S GREAT. THE BISCUITS
ARE REALLY NICE AND LIGHT.
THE GRAVY'S GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE TO IT
FROM THE PEPPER
AND THE HOT SAUCE. MMM.
NICE JOB, MAN. EXCELLENT.
THE GRAVY IS AWESOME.
THE BISCUITS ARE
TO DIE FOR.
THESE ARE THE BEST,
BY FAR.
THE BISCUITS AND GRAVY
IS WHAT I FELL IN LOVE WITH.
MY AUNT HAD BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 30-SOMETHING YEARS,
AND I'M KEEPING
THE TRADITION GOING.
(Guy) ONE BISCUIT
AT A TIME.
EXACTLY.
YOU HEAR THAT A LOT
AROUND HERE.
GENERATIONS OF MY FAMILY
HAVE BEEN COMING HERE.
IT'S DEFINITELY A LANDMARK
IN SALT LAKE CITY.
IT'S A THROWBACK
TO THE '30s.
ORDER UP!
AND OLD-TIME COOKIN'...
MMM.
BUT ALSO A WHOLE LOT MORE,
LIKE CHARBROILED SALMON
AND JAMAICAN CHICKEN.
THEY HAVE SUCH A WIDE
RANGE OF STUFF.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVIN',
BROTHER?
RASPBERRY CHICKEN, AND THE SAUCE
IS RICH AND CREAMY.
JUST TASTES LIKE, MMM,
A LITTLE PIECE OF HEAVEN.
WHAT IS YOUR FAVORITE
THING ON THE MENU?
THE PORK TENDERLOIN.
THIS IS SOMETHING
MY WIFE CAME UP WITH.
A LITTLE BRANDY...
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE HEAVY CREAM.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
MMM. SAUCY AND CREAMY.
WOW, THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
IT'S GREAT.
I'VE ENJOYED IT.
IT'S RIGHT ON PAR WITH
EVERYTHING ELSE THEY SERVE HERE.
THEY'RE JUST MAKING
GOOD FOOD.
(man) MACARONI UP!
KIDS ORDER MACARONI AND CHEESE.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
GOOD AS MY MOM MAKES.
ON THE MENU IT SAYS
"BETTER THAN YOUR MAMA MAKES."
BETTER THAN MY MOM MADE, YEAH.
REALLY?
OH, YEAH, MY MOM'S
GONNA BE WATCHING THIS.
HOW MUCH DO YOU WANT
TO BUY THAT TAPE FOR?
YEAH.
WE'VE GOT SOME OIL HERE.
THROW ON SOME ONIONS,
SAUTé 'EM UP.
A LITTLE FLOUR
WILL MAKE A ROUX.
4 CUPS OF MILK,
4 CUPS OF HEAVY CREAM.
PAPRIKA.
PAPRIKA, BAY LEAVES, SALT...
OH, THAT'S KIND OF LIKE
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL, AIN'T IT?
PEPPER.
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
ELBOW RIGATE
COOKED AL DENTE.
IN THE POOL.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, I LIKE WHERE
THIS IS GOING SO FAR.
COTTAGE CHEESE.
THAT'S THE KICKER.
A LITTLE TANG TO IT.
KEEPS IT MOIST.
AND THEN CHEDDAR
AND MONTEREY JACK CHEESE.
PUT HALF OF THIS IN HERE,
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LAYER OF CHEESE,
THEN THE REST OF THE MACARONI
AND THE REST OF THE CHEESE.
AND WE'RE GONNA TOSS SOME
BREADCRUMBS IN BUTTER.
IT'LL BE A REAL NICE
CRUNCH ON TOP OF THIS.
THAT IS GONNA BE GOOD.
WE'RE JUST GONNA SHOOT
THIS IN THE OVEN.
350 FOR HALF AN HOUR?
YES, SIR.
THAT IS NICE-LOOKIN'.
OH, LOOK,
A COUPLE OF FORKS.
CHEESY.
REALLY GOOD FLAVOR.
PHENOMENAL NOODLE CHOICE.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
EVERYONE WHO COMES HERE IS JUST
REALLY EXCITED TO BE HERE.
THE FOOD IS THAT GOOD.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT
YOU GET HERE, IT'S GREAT.
EXPECT TO BE WOWED.
YOU GOTTA DIG IT, MAN.
GREAT HISTORY TO THIS PLACE.
I LOVE IT.
SHE SENT THE E-MAIL?
YOU BET.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO BE?
YEAH.
I KNEW YOUR CAR WOULD LOOK
GREAT IN FRONT OF THIS PLACE.
UH-HUH.
SO NOW YOU'RE GAMING
FOR A RIDE, REDHEAD?
I LIKE THE WAY
SHE ROLLS.
NEXT STOP...
IT'S A PRETTY
UNIQUE DINER.
MIDDLETOWN, CONNECTICUT...
CHEESEBURGER.
WHERE THE BURGERS
GET STEAMED...
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
THAT YOU CAN HAVE
WHEN YOU'RE IN NEW ENGLAND.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
REALLY GOOD.
AND HASH IS A FOOD GROUP
OF ITS OWN.
BRISKET HASH,
WILD TURKEY HASH.
CLAM HASH.
DUCK HASH.
THIS IS HASH-A-LISTIC.
YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE "D"
WE'RE ALL ABOUT FINDING
THE REAL DEAL
LOCAL FAVORITES,
SO HERE I AM
IN MIDDLETOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WHERE THERE'S A PLACE THAT'S
LOVED BY THE LOCALS SO MUCH
THAT AFTER IT BURNT DOWN,
THEY HELPED RAISE
OVER $300,000
TO HELP THE OWNER
REBUILD THE PLACE.
IT'S CALLED O'ROURKE'S,
AND AFTER DOZENS
OF YOU E-MAILED ME,
YOU KNOW I JUST GOTTA
CHECK IT OUT.
(man) BANANA BREAD
FRENCH TOAST.
THE FOOD IS SPECIAL.
DUCK HASH.
IT'S A PRETTY
UNIQUE DINER.
THERE IS NO PLACE
BETTER THAN O'ROURKE'S
FOR UNIQUE FOOD.
WOW.
I HAD THE DUCK HASH.
IT'S JUST GREAT.
STEAMED BURGER?
STEAMED CHEESEBURGER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
REALLY GOOD.
WE'VE BECOME REAL BIG FANS OF
THIS DINER BECAUSE OF BRIAN.
BRIAN'S AN ARTIST
WITH FOOD.
EGGS.
THAT WOULD BE BRIAN O'ROURKE.
THIS IS YOUR DOMAIN.
YEAH. I'VE GOT
A HALIBUT HASH HERE.
1958, I STARTED WORKING
PEELING POTATOES...
PUT IT UP.
WHATEVER NEEDED
TO BE DONE.
BACK THEN,
BRIAN WAS STILL IN SCHOOL...
HOW YOU DOIN'?
WORKING FOR HIS UNCLE JOHN,
WHO STARTED O'ROURKE'S IN '41.
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
IN '76 I BOUGHT THE DINER.
AND THEN BRIAN TOOK IT
TO ANOTHER LEVEL.
CAN YOU SEE ME?
ARE YOU THERE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT ON IT?
HE WENT FROM A DINER
TO BECOMING A GOURMET DINER.
VERY INTERESTING
COMBINATIONS.
(Brian) THERE'S NO END
WHAT CAN HAPPEN WITH HASH.
CLAM HASH.
BRISKET HASH,
WILD TURKEY HASH,
CORNED BEEF HASH AND A VEGETABLE
HASH--ALWAYS ON THE MENU.
I'M HAVING SMOKED DUCK.
HELL OF A HASH. SO GOOD.
THEY TOLD ME YOU LIKE HASH.
OH, I LOVE HASH.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE BEEN TO
CONNECTICUT AND HAD DUCK HASH.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A MARINADE?
SOME ORANGE JUICE...
BALSAMIC VINEGAR...
OLIVE OIL...
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE CORIANDER...
ROSEMARY.
A LITTLE SAGE...
GOT THE THYME?
SALT AND SOME PEPPER. HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA MARINATE, BOSS?
A DAY.
DO YOU OFTEN USE DUCK
HERE AT THE DINER?
WE USUALLY HAVE
SMOKED DUCK ON THE MENU.
WE SMOKE IT RIGHT HERE.
WE HAVE A PERFORATED HOTEL PAN.
THERE YOU GO. THROW SOME
CHIPS IN THE BOTTOM.
I'M GETTING ON
MY GOGGLES.
SKIN SIDE DOWN.
THERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT. WHOO!
IT'S LIKE
A NELLY VIDEO IN HERE.
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
I LOVE IT. I MEAN, I CAN
ALREADY GET THE PERFUME OF IT,
AND ADDING THAT
TO THE DUCK--
THEN THAT'S GONNA GO
INTO THE HASH.
OH, THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
A LOT OF HASH INGREDIENTS.
THESE ARE TURNIPS
DONE WITH OATMEAL
AND HONEY AND SWEET SAVORY.
THESE ARE THE HAM HOCKS.
WE RAN A PORK LOIN
SPECIAL LAST NIGHT.
SOME PEOPLE MAKE SOUP
OUT OF IT, YOU MAKE HASH.
THIS IS SOME COLCANNON.
COLCANNON IS A POTATO DISH
INDIGENOUS TO A CERTAIN
REGION IN IRELAND.
IT'S DONE WITH CABBAGE, ONIONS
AND CARAWAY, SALT AND PEPPER.
OH.
IT'S CONSTANTLY
IN THE HOUSE.
THAT'S SO GOOD.
JALAPEñO BACON.
THESE ARE THE DUCK BREASTS
AFTER BEING SMOKED.
I DON'T PUT
THE SKINS IN THERE.
NO. SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA TEAR
THAT DUCK BREAST APART.
I DON'T LIKE TO DICE TOO MUCH,
'CAUSE YOU DICE,
IT LOOKS TOO UNIFORM.
CHECK THAT OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S GREAT DUCK.
FRESH CORN...
BROCCOLI RABE.
BROCCOLI RABE,
RED ONIONS AND GARLIC.
LOOK AT THAT.
A HANDFUL OF...
SOME IRISH STEW.
THIS IS HASH-A-LISTIC.
I LIKE THIS.
YOU COOKED IT IN RISOTTO.
THAT'S REALLY GONNA BIND IT UP.
EGGS.
THERE YOU GO.
PUT SOME SPEARMINT,
SOME SAGE IN HERE...
SALT AND PEPPER.
TOASTED HAZELNUTS.
PROBABLY THE MOST UNIQUE HASH
YOU'VE EVER SEEN ON TRIPLE "D."
A LITTLE BACON GREASE.
OH--GOODNESS.
PUT A LITTLE CRUST ON IT.
I DIG IT. APPLE BUTTER.
AND THESE ARE
THE DUCK CRACKLIN'S.
AM I SUPPOSED
TO BE DIPPING IN--
A LITTLE BIT
WOULD BE GOOD.
JUST ROUND IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
MMM.
BOY, THIS IS GOOD.
WITHOUT QUESTION,
THAT IS THE FUNKIEST HASH
I'VE EVER SEEN ON TRIPLE "D."
I THINK THE DUCK'S MY
FAVORITE PART. AND THE CORN.
I NEVER THOUGHT OF CORN
IN HASH.
THAT'S FUNKY DELICIOUS.
MMM.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S JUST FABULOUS.
THIS IS SO GOOD.
CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
BUT I HAD NEVER
THOUGHT OF DUCK,
AND THAT'S WHAT I LOVE
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
THE FOOD HAS CHARACTER.
THE BUILDING HAS CHARACTER.
BUT IN 2006,
THEY ALMOST LOST IT
FOREVER.
WE HAD A FIRE HERE
A COUPLE YEARS AGO.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
LIKE LOSING YOUR HOME.
IT WAS.
AND IT TOOK EVERYTHING OUT.
TOOK EVERYTHING.
THE STRUCTURE STAYED.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE JUST
DIDN'T WANT IT TO GO AWAY,
AND SAID, "YOU KNOW WHAT, WE
GOTTA PUT A COMMITTEE TOGETHER
AND BRING THE DINER BACK."
SCHOOLS AND ALL DIFFERENT
GROUPS RAISED MONEY FOR HIM.
GIVE ME A COPY.
AND A YEAR AND A HALF LATER...
...SOME PEOPLE SMILE.
THEY GOT THEIR DINER BACK,
AND MORE.
SINCE HE'S REOPENED,
HE'S BEEN ABLE TO HAVE A KIND OF
FREEDOM WITH THE MENU.
THE BREAKFAST MENU
IS ABOUT EIGHT PAGES.
WITH 30 DIFFERENT OMELETS.
ETHAN'S IDEAL OMELET--
PROSCIUTTO, SPINACH,
PEARS AND BLUE CHEESE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
EGGS BENEDICT.
14 DIFFERENT KINDS.
EGGS OSCAR.
SHRIMP, ASPARAGUS.
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
DELICIOUS.
BANANA BREAD FRENCH TOAST.
WE HAVE FIVE DIFFERENT
FRENCH TOASTS ON THE MENU.
WE'LL DO A BASIC
BANANA BREAD FRENCH TOAST.
WITH, YEAH,
HOMEMADE BANANA BREAD.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE ACTUAL
BATTER FOR THE FRENCH TOAST.
GOT EGGS DOWN.
VANILLA SUGAR. THAT MUCH.
LITTLE, LITTLE LOVIN'.
PINOT GRIGIO
VANILLA EXTRACT.
THEN WE'LL GIVE IT
SOME SPICE.
SO THIS IS DONE NOW?
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT,
NICE AND DENSE.
I'M GONNA MAKE SOME BANANAS
O'ROURKE TO GO OVER THE TOP.
BANANAS O'ROURKE?
I'M GONNA COOK
THESE DOWN.
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR, A LITTLE
CRèME de BANANA-NA-NA-NA,
A LITTLE BIT OF
CINNAMON THERE.
IRISH WHISKEY.
TAKE A LOOKIE-LOO
AT THAT. (whistles)
BON APPéTIT.
WOW. DELICIOUS.
REALLY GOOD. NOT OVERLY SWEET,
GREAT TEXTURE OF THE BREAD.
IF YOU HAVE ANY INTEREST
IN FRENCH TOAST,
THAT COULD BE
YOUR FAVORITE.
ALMOST LIKE
A DESSERT BREAKFAST.
DELICIOUS.
THERE'S SO MANY
THINGS THAT YOU CAN HAVE.
IT'S INSANE.
YOU THINK?
HOW ABOUT THIS?
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A MACHINE
TO STEAM THE CHEESEBURGER IN.
OF COURSE YOU WOULD,
MR. WONKA.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
O'ROURKE'S DINER HAS BEEN
A MIDDLETOWN, CONNECTICUT,
TRADITION...
CHEESEBURGER.
FOR 67 YEARS.
YOU WALK AWAY WITH ONE
DELICIOUS MEAL AFTER ANOTHER.
THE FOOD IS SPECIAL.
LIKE NO OTHER DINER.
ROBIN JACKSON'S ONE OF MORE
THAN A DOZEN FOLKS
WHO E-MAILED...
IT'S AMAZING.
AND SAID CHECK IT OUT
FOR THE HASH...
WOW.
THE PANCAKES...
STEAMED CHEESEBURGER.
AND THIS LOCAL TRADITION.
IT'S A MIDDLETOWN
AREA THING.
STEAMED CHEESEBURGER
IS UP.
THERE'S ONLY A FEW PLACES AROUND
HERE THAT REALLY MAKE THEM.
IT'S DEFINITELY ONE OF THE BEST
THINGS THAT YOU CAN HAVE
WHEN YOU'RE IN NEW ENGLAND.
HOW DOES HE RATE
HERE AT O'ROURKE'S?
I THINK O'ROURKE'S
IS THE BEST.
REALLY?
THAT LITTLE BOX RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE STEAMED.
THESE LITTLE TRAYS RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS GROUND ANGUS.
AN 80/20 COUNT?
I THINK IT'S ABOUT
84/16.
OKAY. PRETTY PRECISE.
THIS HERE IS
AN AGED CHEDDAR.
MINIMUM AGE--1 YEAR.
REALLY?
WE PUT IT IN THE STEAMER. CHEESE
TAKES A LITTLE BIT OF TIME
TO MELT IT DOWN.
HAMBURGERS BEFORE LUNCH--
THEY'LL LOAD THE BOX UP AND PUT
AS MANY AS THEY POSSIBLY CAN
IN THERE.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
TO STEAM THEM?
FOUR OR FIVE MINUTES WILL
GIVE YOU A NICE MEDIUM ONE.
NOW WHERE DOES ONE
GET ONE OF THESE?
THAT'S HANDMADE. THAT ONE THERE
IS PROBABLY ABOUT 30 YEARS OLD.
NO.
THAT'S SWEET.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS.
THE OLD TIMERS,
WHAT THEY USED TO DO IS...
THEN POUR A LITTLE BIT
OF ITS OWN FAT ON THERE,
A LITTLE MOISTURE.
OUT COMES THE CHEESE.
OH, I GOTTA GET
ONE OF THESE THINGS.
THE TRADITIONAL WAY TO HAVE
THESE IS WITH MUSTARD AND ONION.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THAT CHEESE MAKES IT. YOU
REALLY TASTE THE BEEF IN THAT.
IS THERE ANY SEASONING
IN THE MEAT?
NO, THAT'S JUST THE WAY
IT'S GROUND FOR US.
REALLY? DYNAMITE ROLL.
WE BAKE THE ROLLS
EVERY DAY.
SURE MAKES A DIFFERENCE,
THOUGH, DOESN'T IT?
OH, ALL THE DIFFERENCE
IN THE WORLD.
SO THE WHOLE THING
WAS STEAMED?
EXCEPT THE ROLL.
THE ROLL CAME OFF THE GRILL.
TYPICALLY YOU STEAM THE ROLL
AND YOU PUT
THE BURGER ON THE GRILL.
HERE THEY STEAM THE BURGER
AND PUT THE ROLL ON THE GRILL.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
I LOVE THEM.
IT'S GOT A LOT
OF CHEESE ON IT.
IT'S GOOD.
THERE IS SOMETHING ABOUT THAT
THICK GLOB OF CHEDDAR CHEESE
ON THERE THAT'S
REALLY SATISFYING.
GLOB.
BETTER THAN THOSE OTHER
PLACES THAT MAKE BURGERS?
REALLY?
I MEAN, LIKE, REALLY REALLY?
DO YOU ALWAYS HAVE
THE SAME THING?
NO. THERE'S SO
MANY GOOD THINGS.
WHY DID YOU E-MAIL ME?
I JUST THOUGHT
YOU HAD TO COME HERE.
AND THIS SURPASSES
ALL OTHERS?
RIGHT.
WITH RADICCHIO.
IT'S OUR KIND OF PLACE.
REALLY, REALLY BETTER THAN
ALL OF THE OTHER PLACES?
YES.
HE SAID IT.
SO YOU THOUGHT AS YOU SAT
AND WATCHED IT BURN
THAT YOU WERE GONNA REBUILD?
I MAY HAVE STAYED HERE
AND JUST SOLD STEAMED
CHEESEBURGERS ON THE CORNER.
IT'S MY HOME.
GOOD LUCK.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE "D"--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SEE? IT DOESN'T COME UP.
WHAT WAS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW!
HOW'S THAT ONE?
OH, MY GOSH.