HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
97.
(Guy) THIS TRIP,
ALL KINDS OF FAST FOOD
IN SANTA FE...
GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGER.
54 YEARS
OF THIS LOCAL CLASSIC...
THAT'S THE BEST HAMBURGER
IN SANTA FE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THEY'RE BRINGING THEIR KIDS TO
KNOW WHAT THEY GREW UP LOVING.
AND SOME
NEW CLASSICS, TOO...
KOBE BEEF BURGER.
THE BISON BURGER.
(woman) THE LAMB BURGER.
THAT WAS GOOD.
IN FAIRFIELD, CONNECTICUT...
ONE WITH MUSTARD,
ONE WITH CHILI.
THE FIXINGS MAKE
ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
WHERE A SERIOUS CHEF...
WATCH IT.
IS DOING HIS TAKE
ON HOT DOGS...
THE CHICAGO.
MMM, MMM, MMM.
(man) DILL PICKLE
WITH A HOT RELISH.
THE PICKLE MAKES IT,
MWAH.
AND I'M DOING MY TAKE, TOO.
IT'S CALLED "FRANKENSTEIN."
MMM.
IS THAT KILLER,
OR WHAT?
AND IN OMAHA...
BEEF TACO COMING UP.
WHERE THEY'RE PACKIN' IN...
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
FOR DEEP-FRIED TACOS.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE
LIKE IT.
DONE FRESH...
I WANT EVERYTHING
COOKED THAT DAY.
FAST...
POWER IT UP.
AND ONE AT A TIME.
YOU COULD MAKE 'EM AHEAD OF TIME
IN JUST WAX PAPER.
COULD. DON'T.
MMM, THAT'S KILLER!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
BACK IN 1954,
BEFORE BURGER JOINTS
TURNED INTO BURGER CHAINS,
IT WAS ICONIC PLACES LIKE THIS
THAT SET ONE TOWN
APART FROM ANOTHER,
LIKE HERE
IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO,
WHERE FOR 54 YEARS, BERT'S
BURGER BOWL HAS BEEN ROCKING 'EM
WITH A GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGER.
WORLD-FAMOUS BERT'S BURGER BOWL
GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S HOME-COOKED FAST FOOD.
AND I HAVE TO HAVE ONE
ONCE A WEEK.
WE'RE NOT TALKIN'
CHILI AND BEANS.
WE'RE TALKING GREEN CHILES.
IT'S A NEW MEXICO FLAVOR.
DOES EVERYBODY DO
A GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGER?
EVERYBODY DOES
THEIR VERSION OF IT,
BUT THIS IS THE LANDMARK.
GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGER...
ONE OF THE FIRST
SINCE 1954.
97.
THE PLACE TO COME.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR ABOUT 25 YEARS.
OKAY.
AND OWNERS DEBBIE OLEA...
ONE CHEESEBURGER.
AND HER HUSBAND FERNANDO...
THREE CHILE CHEESEBURGERS.
ARE PROUD
TO BE KEEPING THIS LANDMARK
THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
NO ONION, NO TOMATO.
IT'S A NICE HOT BURGER.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE NAME OF THIS CHILE
IS GREEN CHILE HATCH.
THIS IS THE SPICY.
THEY HAVE A SPECIAL FLAVOR,
AND THE ONLY WAY THAT YOU
CAN FIND THESE IS IN NEW MEXICO.
BECAUSE WE USE
A BIG AMOUNT OF CHILES,
WE BUY THESE ALREADY PROCESSED--
120 POUNDS OF CHILES...
OF CHILES?
A WEEK, YES.
NOW IS THIS
THE CLAIM TO FAME?
IS THIS WHAT'S MADE BERT'S
SO GREAT?
THAT'S WHY PEOPLE KEEP COMING
TO BERT'S FOR THE LAST 54 YEARS.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO WITH THESE?
WE'RE GONNA POUR OUR GREEN
CHILES INTO THIS LARGE POT.
THEN WHAT?
GARLIC POWDER,
GRANULATED ONION, SALT.
A LITTLE SALT.
AND WE FINISH WITH A LITTLE
PINCH OF OREGANO.
A LITTLE PINCH OF OREGANO.
CAN THIS
MAKE A DIFFERENCE?
JUST A LITTLE TOUCH.
IT'S A KISS.
IT'S JUST A KISS.
OKAY.
BUT A KISS
IS JUST A KISS.
WE'RE GONNA
LET IT SIMMER.
FOR HOW LONG?
JUST SIMMER APPROXIMATELY
45 MINUTES, AN HOUR.
IS THIS READY TO TRY?
IT IS, YES.
WOW. IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF SPICE TO IT, NICE WARMTH.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
I SHOULD EAT IT
LIKE THIS.
YES.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY THEY CALL
IT "HAMBURGER HELPER."
WE PUT GREEN CHILI
ON EVERYTHING.
IT'S PART OF OUR CULTURE.
THE CHILE CHEESEBURGER IS IT,
SO LET'S MAKE ONE OF THOSE.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO FOR IT.
START WITH THE BUN,
PUT IT ON THE GRILL
BECAUSE WE LIKE IT
LIKE THAT.
WE LIKE IT LIKE THAT?
WE LIKE IT LIKE THAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GET ONE
OF OUR HOMEMADE PATTIES,
A LITTLE SALT,
THAT'S IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE CONDIMENTS--
MUSTARD, LETTUCE, TOMATO,
ONION, MUSTARD ON TOP,
BECAUSE THAT'S GONNA
HOLD OUR PICKLES.
THE MUSTARD
HOLDS YOUR PICKLES?
HOLD MY PICKLES
TO THE BUN.
SO WE'RE GONNA JUST FLIP IT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT OUR CHILE ON.
CHEESE.
IT'S READY?
IT IS READY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL, MY MAN.
SINK YOUR TEETH
INTO THAT, GUY.
UH-OH,
YOU'RE THINKING TOO HARD.
NO, I'M JUST MAKING SURE YOU
DON'T TRY TO GET IN ON A BITE.
MMM, THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT CHILE IS CRAZY.
IT'S SUCH
A GREAT ACCENT.
IT IS.
IT'S NOT SPICY
LIKE TOO HOT.
NO.
IT COMPLEMENTS IT.
EXACTLY.
LOOK AT THAT.
DON'T INTERRUPT ME WITH ANY BUN.
I WANT MEAT,
CHILE, CHEESE.
DUDE, YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
THIS IS BANANAS.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
IT'S THE BEST HAMBURGER
IN SANTA FE.
IT'S TANGY.
IT'S HOT.
HOW MUCH IS THIS?
IT'S 3 DOLLARS AND 50 CENTS,
A BARGAIN.
MMM.
93, AND THERE IS 94.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A GREAT
NEIGHBORHOOD RESTAURANT.
YOU TYPICALLY SEE
SOMEBODY YOU KNOW.
THE LOCALS ARE THE ONES
THAT HAVE KEPT THIS PLACE
VIBRANT AND ALIVE.
LOOK AT THAT--GORGEOUS.
HOW LONG YOU
BEEN COMIN' HERE?
OH, ABOUT 40 YEARS.
THEY'RE BRINGING THEIR KIDS TO
KNOW WHAT THEY GREW UP LOVING.
IT'S JUST SIMPLE AND QUICK
FINE EATING.
'CAUSE DEBBIE AND FERNANDO
AREN'T FIXIN' WHAT AIN'T BROKE.
CHILE CHEESEBURGER
AND A SMALL FRY.
BUT THEY'RE INVENTING
A FEW THINGS.
THEY'VE GOT
THE BISON BURGER.
MMM.
KOBE BEEF BURGER.
IT'S GREAT.
THIS IS A PORT BURGER.
OH, WOW.
MMM.
IT'S GOT TREMENDOUS FLAVOR.
NOT GAMY.
SPICES COMPLEMENT IT WELL.
NICE.
IT'S YUMMY.
IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
WE ARE GOING TO FINISH OFF
WITH THE CROWD-PLEASER,
WHICH IS THE LAMB
1/2-POUND BURGER.
REALLY GOOD BURGER,
REALLY TENDER.
HAD A LOAD OF TASTE.
I CAN'T WAIT.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA MAKE NOW IS
THE SAUCE FOR OUR LAMB BURGER.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR LIME.
SEE, RIGHT NOW, WE COULD
BE MAKING A MARGARITA.
WE COULD GO
THE WHOLE OTHER DIRECTION.
IT COULD BE.
THAT WOULD BE VERY NICE.
BUT THE VINEGAR--
YOU JUST WRECKED IT.
VINEGAR--THAT WOULD RUIN
OUR MARGARITA.
AND THE GARLIC--YEAH.
GARLIC, WELL...
WE'RE NOT GOIN' THERE.
NOW WHAT, OREGANO?
OREGANO, ONION, SALT.
ARE THESE
THE RED CHILIES AGAIN,
OR ARE THESE GUAJILLOS?
NO, THESE ARE GUAJILLOS.
THESE ARE GUAJILLOS.
NOW WE'RE NOT GONNA STEEP THESE
IN WATER OR ANYTHING?
NO.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
GRIND 'EM RIGHT UP?
JUST GONNA DO IT DIRECTLY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GET THIS
TO THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF WATER,
AND WE'RE GONNA BLEND
ALL OF OUR INGREDIENTS.
SO YOU'RE JUST
GONNA LIQUEFY THIS THING.
OH, YES, YES, YES, YES.
AND THAT'S IT.
WE'RE GONNA INCORPORATE THIS
INTO OUR GROUND LAMB.
WOW, IT SMELLS GOOD.
AND TASTES BETTER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LOT
OF OREGANO.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WHAT DOES THIS DISH
COME FROM?
THIS DISH COMES
FROM A TACO IN MéJICO
THAT IS CALLED
TACO PASTOR.
AL PASTOR?
YES.
OH, I LOVE AL PASTOR.
BUT AL PASTOR I SEE,
SOMETIMES PEOPLE
ARE PUTTING PINEAPPLE IN IT.
THAT'S THE WAY THAT WE DO
THE REST OF OUR HAMBURGER.
PUT THE PINEAPPLE
ON THE FLAT GRILL
JUST TO SEAR IT
A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
THIS IS ABOUT
READY TO GO.
I LIKE IT.
LET'S GET
THE CILANTRO GOING.
IT'S A BIG BURGER.
IT'S VERY BIG.
CLOSE IT UP.
SO NO MAYO,
NO SOUR CREAM?
NO MAYO, NO NOTHING.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOT EXACTLY THE BURGER
I EXPECTED TO FIND
WHEN I DROVE UP TO A PLACE
THAT'S BEEN 54 YEARS--
A LAMB BURGER
WITH AL PASTOR
AND SOME GRILLED PINEAPPLE
AND SOME CILANTRO.
GO FOR IT.
THAT'S GOOD.
NOT TOO SPICY,
GOOD LAMB FLAVOR,
AND THE PINEAPPLE--
THE SWEETNESS--BALANCES IT OUT.
A LOT DIFFERENT THAN
A HAMBURGER, A LOT MORE JUICY.
IT'S JUST THE FLAVOR.
THE FOOD IS JUST EXCELLENT.
CLOSE BY.
GOOD PRICES.
MAY I HELP YOU?
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
THEY SEE ME COMING.
THEY KNOW WHAT I WANT.
THE BEST THING HERE
ON THE MENU IS WHAT?
THE GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGERS.
SO THIS IS WHAT
YOU HAVE EVERY TIME.
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
THE GUY KNOWS
WHAT HE LIKES.
IF SOMEBODY COMES TO SANTA FE
AND DOESN'T MAKE THEIR STOP
AT BERT'S BURGER BOWL,
THEY ARE MISSING SOMETHING.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
GOING TO LOS ANGELES
BUT NOT HITTIN' DISNEYLAND.
EXACTLY.
YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN GREAT.
THANK YOU.
OH.
GOT A CALIFORNIAN.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO CONNECTICUT...
THANK YOU.
THE FIXINGS
MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
FOR SERIOUS COOKING
AT A HOT DOG JOINT.
SPICY BROWN MUSTARD,
SWEET RELISH...
AHH.
CHOPPED ONIONS--
THERE YOU GO.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
NOW I'VE BEEN HEARING A LOT
ABOUT A PLACE
CALLED SUPER DUPER WEENIE
IN CONNECTICUT.
I HAVE FRIENDS THAT LIVE
IN CONNECTICUT--ALEX AND STEVE--
AND THEY INVITED ME OVER
TO THEIR HOUSE
ONE NIGHT FOR DINNER.
NOW WHAT COMES ROLLIN'
DOWN THE DRIVEWAY FOR DINNER
BUT THIS--
THE SUPER DUPER WEENIE WAGON.
I'M TELLIN' YOU,
I DID SOME GREAT FIELD-TESTING,
AND THAT'S WHAT BRINGS US HERE
TO FAIRFIELD, CONNECTICUT,
TO THE SUPER DUPER WEENIE
WORLD HEADQUARTERS.
ONE WITH MUSTARD,
ONE WITH CHILI.
THE HOT DOGS ARE THE BEST.
IF YOU WANT
A REAL SERIOUS,
AUTHENTIC
OLD-FASHIONED HOT DOG...
SUPER DUPER
IS THE PLACE TO COME.
'CAUSE GARY ZEMOLA...
CHICAGO.
IS SERIOUS ABOUT HIS DOGS...
SO YOU'RE
THE BIG WEENIE HERE?
A CULINARY SCHOOL GRAD
WHO FELL IN LOVE
WITH AN OLD HOT DOG TRUCK...
WHEN I FOUND THE TRUCK,
IT WAS BACK IN 1991.
I TOOK IT AND GUTTED IT,
REDID IT.
GOT A CALIFORNIAN.
AND STARTED DOING HOT DOGS
HIS WAY.
ONE NEW YORK.
IT'S JUST A SPECIAL HOT DOG.
THEY SLICE IT
AND COOK IT ON THE GRILL.
WE LIKE TO GET
A NICE BROWNING ON THEM,
GET 'EM
A LITTLE CRISPY.
THAT'S THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN HERE
AND ANY OTHER HOT DOG STAND.
THAT AND THE SCRATCH-MADE
TOPPINGS...
IT'S NOT OPENING PACKAGES.
YOU MAKE ALL THIS.
YES.
FROM SWEET RELISH
TO HOT RELISH TO CHILI...
THE FIXINGS
MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
ON ALL KINDS OF COMBOS.
THE NEW YORKER
HAS THE SAUERKRAUT
AND THE SPICY RELISH.
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE DIXIE DOG--
CHILI AND COLESLAW--
WHAT A COMBINATION.
THE CHICAGO...
MMM, MMM, MMM.
DILL PICKLE
WITH A HOT RELISH.
THE PICKLE MAKES IT,
MWAH.
ARE YOU READY FOR 'EM?
AND FOLKS JUST COULDN'T
GET ENOUGH OF 'EM...
THANK YOU.
THE TRUCK JUST
GOT TO BE OVERWHELMING.
I COULD NOT KEEP UP.
SO GARY
OPENED THIS JOINT...
WORLD HEADQUARTERS
OF SUPER DUPER WEENIE.
WHERE THEY'RE TURNING OUT
2,000 DOGS A WEEK.
GOT A NEW ENGLANDER. TOP-SELLING
DOG IS A NEW ENGLANDER.
THE BACON, THE SAUERKRAUT, AND I
LIKE THE SWEET RELISH A LOT.
LIKE A TYPICAL PICKLE RELISH
BUT FRESH.
CUCUMBER TAKES
A BIG ROLE IN THIS.
YES,
IT'S A SWEET CUCUMBER RELISH--
CHOPPED, TOSSED
WITH SOME KOSHER SALT.
LET 'EM SIT OVERNIGHT,
GET ALL THE WATER OUT.
RED AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
CUCUMBERS, ONIONS...
MOM KNOWS
YOU STOLE HER BOWL?
THIS HAD AMBROSIA SALAD
IN IT LAST WEEK.
MUSTARD SEED,
CELERY SEED, SUGAR...
THIS IS CIDER VINEGAR,
WATER.
WE'RE GONNA BRING THIS UP
TO A SIMMER. SHUT IT OFF.
I STILL WANT IT
A LITTLE CRISPY.
THAT'S BANANAS.
THAT'S RELISH.
I'M GONNA
GIVE IT A BLEND.
SO YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE
A LITTLE TEXTURE TO IT.
OH, YEAH.
NOW DO WE TASTE IT?
I KNOW WHY THEY CALL IT RELISH.
YOU RELISH THAT.
AND THIS IS GONNA
GO ON WHAT AGAIN?
THE NEW ENGLANDER.
WHEN BUILDING
THIS HOT DOG...
THE "QUINTESSENTIAL."
THE QUINTESSENTIAL.
THAT'S WHAT
I LIKE TO CALL IT.
YOU'RE STARTING OFF WITH A NICE
BIG SLICE OF BACON, KRAUT.
PEOPLE ARE GONNA COME IN AND ASK
HIM WHAT "QUINTESSENTIAL" MEANS.
JUST A REAL GOOD SPICY
BROWN MUSTARD, SWEET RELISH...
AHH.
CHOPPED ONIONS--
THERE YOU GO.
IT JUST DOESN'T GET
ANY BETTER THAN THAT.
I HOPE YOU KNOW AT HOME
THAT I EAT THIS FOR YOU.
(grunts)
LET'S GET READY FOR THIS.
MMM. WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
THE HIDDEN SURPRISE
IN ALL OF THAT IS THE BACON.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH--
IT JUST FORTIFIES IT.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE RELISH,
IT TAKES IT ALL JUST--
IT'S THE AMALGAMATOR.
MMM.
WHERE HAS THAT BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
I'VE NEVER TASTED ANYTHING
LIKE THE RELISH.
THE BEST HOT DOG EVER.
UNLESS YOU WANT IT HOT...
THIS IS...
HOT PEPPER RELISH.
NICE AND SPICY.
AND HE'S USING THIS ONE
ON THREE DIFFERENT DOGS.
RED AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
THEY'VE BEEN SALTED
AND DRAINED
TO GET MOST OF THE LIQUID
OUT OF THEM.
SO YOU PUT
THE ONIONS IN.
WATER, RED WINE VINEGAR...
RED WINE VINEGAR.
GARLIC CLOVES...
THERE YOU GO.
FENNEL SEED...
OOH, I LIKE THAT MOVE.
SUGAR.
GOT IT.
A QUICK SIMMER,
AND I SHUT IT OFF.
YOU DON'T WANT IT MUSHY.
HOT CHOPPED
PICKLED CHERRY PEPPERS--
THIS IS WHERE YOU GET THE EXTRA
HEAT AS WELL AS FLAVOR.
RED PEPPER FLAKE
FOR HEAT.
BECAUSE IF IT WASN'T
HOT ENOUGH
WITH THE VINEGAR
AND THE RED PEPPER,
WE'RE GONNA HIT THAT
IN THERE.
RIGHT.
GIVE THIS A SHOT.
GONNA GET
THE PARTY STARTED?
DON'T WANT TO PUT MY FINGER
IN THAT ONE.
THAT'S ABOUT RIGHT.
THAT'LL CLEAR YOU OUT.
MMM.
IT MARRIES TOGETHER NICE.
SO WHAT DO WE PUT THIS ON?
THE NEW YORKER.
I MODELED THIS HOT DOG
AFTER THE DOGS YOU'D FIND
ON THE STREETS OF NEW YORK
OFF A CART.
WE GOT KRAUT, A LITTLE BIT
OF RED ONION SAUCE,
A LITTLE MUSTARD,
A LITTLE BIT OF HOT RELISH.
NICE BALANCE OF SALT
TO SWEET TO HEAT.
MMM!
A BIG FLAVOR.
GOSH, THAT'S GOOD.
I LIKE THE SPLITTING
OF THE GRILLED DOG.
YOU KNOW, LIKE A CRUSTY,
CRUNCHY--MMM!
RIGHT.
THE KRAUT ISN'T AS OVERWHELMING
AS A LOT OF TIMES IT CAN BE.
DO PEOPLE IN NEW YORK
KNOW ABOUT THIS?
THE NEW YORKER IS SAVORY.
I REALLY LIKE IT.
IT'S NOT KILLER HOT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I LOVE THE SAUERKRAUT.
THE SAUERKRAUT
TASTES VERY FRESH.
IT'S DIFFERENT HERE
THAN OTHER PLACES.
YOU FORTIFY IT WITH YOUR OWN
LITTLE GIDDYAP?
RIGHT.
YEP. TAKE A LITTLE CHOPPED
BACON, A LITTLE CARAWAY.
I'M GONNA PUT THAT RIGHT
IN OUR BOWL OF SAUERKRAUT HERE.
IT SMELLS GOOD.
IT'S PROBABLY ONE OF
THE MOST WIDELY USED CONDIMENTS
WE HAVE HERE.
ON THE NEW YORKER,
THE NEW ENGLANDER
AND THE GEORGIA RED HOT.
SOUTHERN-STYLE SAUSAGE,
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR KRAUT,
MUSTARD AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE HOMEMADE SWEET.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M STANDING BACK.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
OKAY.
(laughs)
(chuckles)
(mouths word)
THAT'S HOT.
THAT IS.
BUT THEN YOU GET
THE COOL RELISH
AND SWEET
COUNTERBALANCING IT--MMM--
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF THE VINEGAR COMING THROUGH.
EXCELLENT.
IT'S A PERFECT SPICY HOT DOG,
A PERFECT BITE EVERY TIME.
IF YOU'RE GONNA DO IT,
DO IT RIGHT.
THAT'S WHAT
I WANTED TO DO.
WHATEVER HE'S MAKING...
TWO LARGE FRIES.
THE FRENCH FRIES
ARE TO DIE FOR.
THEY CUT 'EM FRESH
EVERY DAY.
I ATE THE CHEESESTEAK,
AND THAT WAS GREAT.
AND MY KIDS LOVE
THE CHICKEN FINGERS.
THEY DO GREAT
CHICKEN FINGERS.
ARE YOU EATING SOUP, SIR?
I AM. YOU CAN GET THE BEST SOUP
AT SUPER DUPER WEENIE.
BUT DON'T THINK
THEY'VE PARKED THE TRUCK.
CHURCH PICNIC FUNCTIONS,
BIRTHDAY PARTIES--
WE CATER EVERYTHING.
AND WHEN THE WEENIE WAGON
ROLLS OUT...
IT'S EXACTLY
THE SAME DEAL.
SAME THING.
FROM THE CART TO THE RESTAURANT,
IT'S STILL THE SAME HOT DOG.
DARN BEST HOT DOG EVER.
SOMETIMES WITH RELISH, SOMETIMES
WITH BACON--I MAKE UP MY OWN.
CAN I BUILD SOMETHING?
BY ALL MEANS.
THIS IS GONNA GO BIG.
OKAY.
THREE WEENIES, ONIONS,
A COUPLE PIECES OF BACON,
A LITTLE CHEESE.
I'M GONNA TAKE THIS EXAMPLE
FROM OUR BOYS
AT THE SQUEEZE INN
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA.
LOOK AT THAT
CHEESY MELTED GOODNESS, HUH?
DO YOU SEE WHERE
I'M GOING WITH THAT?
CHILI--TWO SCOOPS.
DO YOU FEEL MY PAIN SO FAR?
A DOLLOP OF SLAW.
SPRINKLE IT WITH SOME ONIONS.
SWEET LEFT, HOT RIGHT.
TALK ABOUT THAT.
IT'S CALLED "FRANKENSTEIN."
MMM.
DUDE, THAT'S DYNAMITE.
IS THAT KILLER,
OR WHAT?
YOU KNOW, THE CHILI
AND THE ONIONS AND THE HEAT,
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
YOU GET WHACKED WITH THE SLAW.
LISTEN TO WHO JUST BECAME
THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
VERY NICE.
PLEASE HOLD.
I HAVE TO TAKE ANOTHER BITE.
MMM.
THEY'RE GREAT HOT DOGS.
IT'S NOT YOUR REGULAR
HOT DOG STAND.
YOU'RE ALL SET.
I'M JUST A COOK.
I LIKE TO MAKE GOOD FOOD.
THIS DOES NOT FEEL
LIKE FAST FOOD AT ALL TO ME.
INSTEAD OF JUST GOING
FOR THE ORDINARY,
COME FOR THE EXTRAORDINARY.
THIS IS IT.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY WE DO IT.
THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S LIKE
WHEN THE BIG WEENIE
STARTS TO HAVE A MELTDOWN.
REPRESENT, BROTHER.
GOTTA DO IT.
NEXT STOP...
BEEF TACO COMING UP.
OMAHA...
IT'S FAST, EASY AND UNIQUE.
FOR MEXICAN COOKING
DONE THIS GUY'S WAY.
YOU COULD MAKE 'EM AHEAD OF TIME
IN JUST WAX PAPER.
COULD. DON'T.
THIS ONE'S A GREAT FAMILY STORY.
HERE I AM IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA.
IN 1914, A BELGIAN IMMIGRANT
PUT UP THIS BUILDING
AND OPENED UP A PHARMACY.
HE LATER PASSED IT ON
TO HIS SON.
WELL, DECADES LATER,
HIS SON RETIRES,
AND IT LOOKS LIKE
THE BOGARD FAMILY LEGACY
IS GONNA END ON THIS CORNER...
WELL, THAT IS UNTIL
THE GRANDSON STEPPED UP
AND SAID, "I'LL TAKE A SHOT,"
MOVED BACK FROM MIAMI
AND REOPENED THE PLACE HIS WAY
AS A TAQUERIA.
TWO BEEF HARD-SHELLS.
SERVIN' ALL THE CLASSICS...
CHICKEN CHIMICHANGA--
IT'S GREAT.
BEEF ENCHILADA.
GREAT FOOD.
BUT THE HEAVY HITTER...
ONE MORE BEEF.
IS SOMETHING BRAD BOGARD
CALLS THE CALIFORNIA TACO...
HERE WE GO.
EVEN THOUGH HE DISCOVERED IT
ON A TRIP TO THE CARIBBEAN...
IT'S A PUFFY-SHELL TACO.
THAT HE BROUGHT TO OMAHA...
NO LETTUCE.
WHEN HE DECIDED TO SETTLE DOWN
AND OPEN THIS JOINT
IN THE OLD FAMILY BUILDING.
BEEF TACO COMING UP.
JUST ONE HITCH...
I'VE NEVER WORKED IN
A RESTAURANT BEFORE IN MY LIFE.
NEVER WORKED AT ONE.
WENT DOWN
TO THE MEXICAN GROCERY STORE.
POLLO, CHICKEN?
THEY STARTED
GIVING YOU IDEAS?
YEAH, THEY WOULD POINT
AT WHAT TO USE.
OH, THERE'S
THE TORTILLA RECIPE.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU STARTED
MAKING TORTILLAS.
YEAH.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
START WITH WHEAT FLOUR, GOOD
SEA SALT, BAKING SODA, YEAH...
SO THAT'S GIVING IT
SOME OF THE LEAVENING?
VEGETABLE SHORTENING.
THEN SOME HOT WATER.
CRANK THIS BABY UP.
SO ONCE THE DOUGH WORKS,
DO YOU KNEAD IT?
YOU GOTTA KNEAD THAT DOUGH.
NOW WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO DO THIS?
NOBODY. ME.
REALLY?
THROW MY DOUGH DOWN.
WE PUT IT
IN THE BUN DIVIDER.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHAT IS THAT, CIRCA 1840?
PATENT 1931.
WOW.
INTO THE SLOT.
REFINEMENT RING.
'CAUSE YOU WILL
STAY IN THERE.
PULL IT DOWN. WHEN WE HIT
THE BUTTON. NICE DROP-DOWN.
ACTIVATE.
REALLY?
UP.
WOW, LOOK AT THOSE LITTLE
BISCUITS OF FRIENDSHIP.
NOW YOU GO AHEAD
AND ROLL THESE OUT BY HAND.
EXACTLY.
POWER IT UP, AND WE DON'T DO IT
UNTIL WE GET YOUR ORDER.
OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
YOU COULD MAKE 'EM AHEAD OF TIME
IN JUST WAX PAPER.
COULD. DON'T.
I WANT THEIR TACOS TASTING
LIKE I WANT MY TACOS.
SO THAT'S IT.
NOW WE CAN STUFF IT
WITH WHATEVER WE WANT.
STEAK, CHICKEN, BEEF.
NOW THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE GONNA USE
TO MAKE
THE CARNE ASADA?
STEAK. EXACTLY.
TAKE IT OVER TO THE SLICER.
PUT THE SPICES TOGETHER--
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER, SEA SALT,
ONION SALT, CAYENNE PEPPER
AND OREGANO.
OH, I LIKE
THE SEASONING MIX ON THAT.
AND THEN WE GRILL IT?
OPEN FLAME.
MEDIUM-RARE ON BOTH SIDES
SO IT DOESN'T DRY OUT?
YOU GOT IT.
AND AFTER IT COOLS,
THEN WE SLICE IT.
IF YOU SLICE IT
RIGHT AWAY--
YOU LOSE
ALL THE JUICES.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S SOME
PRETTY GOOD CARNE.
THESE GET POPPED
INSIDE OF HERE?
RIGHT.
THAT'S A HEALTHY
LITTLE PORTION.
AND THAT'S IT.
BYE-BYE, LET'S FRY?
LET'S DO IT.
AFTER IT'S DONE COOKING, LET IT
DRAIN A LITTLE BIT OF THE OIL.
SHOULD WE SEE
WHAT SHE LOOKS LIKE?
THAT TAKES
A LITTLE SOMETHING.
LOOK AT THAT.
LETTUCE--WE SHRED
OUR OWN CHEESE.
QUESO.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
MMM. MEAT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
CRUNCHY--LOOK AT ALL
THE JUICE IN THERE.
MMM, KILLER!
DO I LOOK LIKE I JUST
TOOK A BATH IN THAT, OR WHAT?
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
NICE JOB, MAN.
APPRECIATE THAT.
GOOD TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT A GREAT TASTE TO IT.
IT TASTED HOMEMADE.
MY MOM DIDN'T
MAKE 'EM THIS GOOD.
THAT'S KIND OF LIKE
THE SEAL OF APPROVAL.
WE OUGHT TO MAKE THAT
CHUNG-CHUNG SOUND. CHUNG-CHUNG.
IT'S QUICK, IT'S EASY,
AND IT'S GREAT FOOD.
IT TASTES REALLY FRESH.
I WANT EVERYTHING
COOKED THAT DAY.
THE SALSA'S GREAT.
TWO KINDS--THE RED...
IT TASTES LIKE SOMEBODY
JUST CHOPPED UP A TOMATO
AND PUT IT IN THE BOTTLE.
AND THE GREEN--
MADE WITH FRESH JALAPEñOS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S MONEY.
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
AND BRAD KEEPS SERVIN' UP
ALL THE FAVORITES...
BEEF HARD-SHELL TACOS.
THERE WE GO--BURRITO.
THE NACHOS SUPREME--
REALLY GOOD.
AND WHEN HE HEADS BACK
TO THE FRYER...
CHICKEN CHIMI.
WELL, LET'S MAKE A CHIMICHANGA,
A BIG DEEP-FRIED BURRITO.
EXACTLY.
IT'S 80/20 GROUND BEEF.
ADD THE SEASONINGS RIGHT AFTER
WE GET THE MEAT IN THERE.
ANCHO...
ANCHO CHILI PEPPER...
THE CHIPOTLE, OKAY.
SEA SALT
AND ONION SALT.
ADD A LITTLE WATER.
EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL.
YOU'RE GONNA LET IT SIT HERE
AND COOK FOR WHAT, TWO HOURS?
ABOUT RIGHT AT IT.
SO THAT'S COOKED DOWN.
I MEAN, THAT IS LIKE BEEF SAUCE.
(whistles)
AND THIS IS THE METHOD, HUH?
THE SPICES HELP SEPARATE
THAT OIL FROM THE MEAT.
THAT'S PRECISE.
SO LET THESE COOL DOWN.
THEN WHAT GOES DOWN?
PINTO BEANS.
WE SORT EVERY ONE BY HAND,
LOOKIN' FOR ROCKS.
THE THING I LOVE
IS THAT WHEN YOU WERE HANGIN'
DOWN AT
THE MEXICAN MARKET,
YOU GOT SOME REALLY
PARTICULAR INFORMATION.
SOMETHING LIKE SORTING BEANS,
WHICH IS QUITE AN ART,
VERY SELDOM DONE,
AND THEN YOU COOK THE BEANS.
MIX THE BEANS
INTO THE GROUND BEEF.
JUST A FEW.
FLOUR TORTILLA.
PUT A LITTLE STEAM ON IT
SO IT'S PLIABLE.
EXACTLY. MAKE IT PLIABLE,
SO WE CAN FOLD IT UP.
SO IT DOESN'T CRACK.
A LITTLE REFRIED BEANS,
A GOOD AMOUNT OF MEAT, ONIONS.
YOU KNOW HOW
I LIKE CHEESE.
CHEESY.
LIKE THAT.
ARE WE GONNA WEDGE
THAT IN THERE AGAIN?
THEN OVER TO THE FRYER?
YOU GOT IT.
THERE WE GO.
PLATE IT REAL QUICK.
LETTUCE ON THERE,
CHEESE, A COUPLE OLIVES.
LET'S TAKE A GANDER
AT THAT BAD BOY.
CRISPY OUTSIDE,
CREAMY CHEESY ON THE INSIDE.
MMM. THAT'S AWESOME, MAN.
YOU KNOW MY FAVORITE PART--
THE LITTLE BIT OF ONION
YOU PUT IN THERE.
NICE CRUNCH, ENOUGH CHEESE.
MMM. WELL DONE, BROTHER.
THANKS, BROTHER.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S GOT HOMEMADE FLAVORS YOU
DON'T FIND JUST ANYWHERE ELSE.
ALL THE MEAT AND CHEESE
IS JUST GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY DO IT,
BUT IT'S AMAZING.
YOU'VE GOT
A LOT OF CHOICES.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE
LIKE IT.
AND BRAD
JUST KEEPS ON FRYIN'.
CHICKEN ENCHILADA.
IT DEFINITELY TASTES FRESH
AND HOMEMADE.
LET THESE GUYS
GO TO A COMMERCIAL.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE GONNA
TRY THE ENCHILADAS, RIGHT?
SOUNDS GOOD. EXACTLY.
ONE BEEF TACO.
AT CALIFORNIA TACOS
IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA...
BEEF, CHICKEN, CHICKEN, STEAK.
BRAD BOGARD'S BEEN DOING
SCRATCH-MADE MEXICAN FOOD
HIS WAY FOR 13 YEARS NOW...
YOU CAN TELL IT'S FRESH.
DEEP-FRYING TACOS...
MMM.
AND CHIMICHANGAS AND PANFRYING
SAUCE RIGHT ON THE TORTILLAS
FOR HIS CHICKEN ENCHILADA.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SHREDDED CHICKEN.
CHICKEN DOWN.
A LITTLE SEA SALT
IN THERE...
WATER, JUST ENOUGH
TO COVER IT...
RIGHT.
SIMMER IT
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
LET IT BREAK DOWN.
(whistles)
IT ALMOST STARTS
TO SHRED FOR YOU.
HOW MUCH DOES THAT MAKE
FOR YOU FOR A DAY?
HALF A DAY.
REALLY? AND THEN
YOU'LL DO IT AGAIN?
YEAH.
YOU JUST KEEP GOIN'.
KEEP GOIN'.
SO THE CHICKEN
GETS SHREDDED UP.
WE JUST WANT TO ADD
A LITTLE PUNGENT FLAVOR.
THIS MIXTURE OF CUMIN,
CAYENNE AND PAPRIKA.
AND YOU ROLL IT AROUND.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
THAT'S KILLER.
THAT'S A REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
WE NEED THE SAUCE
FOR THE ENCHILADAS.
START WITH
THE TOMATO SAUCE.
WE'VE GOT SOME
CHILI POWDER--ANCHO.
WELL, THE ANCHO CHILI FARMERS
HERE IN NEBRASKA
ARE DOING REALLY WELL
WITH ALL YOUR USE.
THEN WE ROLL IN...
CHIPOTLE.
ONION SALT, THE SEA SALT,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
A LITTLE AGUA.
YOU LET THAT WARM UP.
THIS IS ONE THING ABOUT MEXICAN
FOOD THAT PEOPLE DON'T KNOW,
IS A LOT OF IT IS PREPARATION--
THE "LOW AND SLOW" IDEA.
LET THAT WARM UP.
YOU TAKE SOME CANOLA OIL.
SAUCE IS HOT--
DIP, FRY, OUT.
PUT IT IN
THE ENCHILADA SAUCE.
HEAT THE TORTILLA
WITH THAT SALSA IN THE OIL.
IT REALLY MAKES THAT ENCHILADA
SAUCE SO FRIED INTO IT...
IT JUST SOAKS
RIGHT INTO IT.
SOAK RIGHT INTO IT, AND THAT
TORTILLA HOLDS THE SAUCE.
DIP, FRY, OUT.
I LIKE THE CONCEPT.
COOK THAT RIGHT INTO IT.
YOU LOOK LIKE
EDWARD SCISSORHANDS WITH THOSE.
WE'RE DOIN' ENCHILADAS.
LOOK AT THAT CHICKEN.
A LITTLE BIT OF CHEESE
INSIDE ALSO.
THEN IT HAS TO GO
THROUGH THE STEAMER.
(steam hisses)
I THINK WE'RE READY.
NICE.
ROLL IT UP HERE.
TOP IT WITH SOME MORE CHEESE.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW I ALWAYS DRESS 'EM
IN LETTUCE,
A COUPLE OF MY HOMEMADE
FLOUR TORTILLA CHIPS.
MMM. IT'S GOOD, MAN. I GOTTA
TELL YOU SOMETHING, DUDE.
THAT TORTILLA CHOKING UP
THAT SAUCE--FANTASTIC FLAVOR.
MMM. A LOT OF CHEESE IN THAT.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD, MAN.
THANK YOU.
THE CHICKEN IS REALLY JUICY.
THE MELTED CHEESE
MAKES IT REALLY GOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S DIFFERENT THAN GOING
TO A FAST FOOD RESTAURANT.
CALIFORNIA TACOS.
IT'S FAST,
EASY AND UNIQUE.
ONE MORE BEEF.
IT'S NOT MADE
TILL I ORDER IT.
COMIN' UP.
IT'S GREAT.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
IT'S ALWAYS, ALWAYS GOOD.
WHAT IS THE FUTURE
OF CALIFORNIA TACO?
THERE'S SOMETHING TO BE SAID
FOR STAYING SMALL.
YOU'RE DOING
SOMETHING RIGHT, BROTHER.
BEING ABLE TO MAKE
THESE PERSONAL CONNECTIONS
WITH MY CUSTOMERS
THAT COME IN.
HEY, HOW WE DOING?
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN.
YOU'VE GOT A GREAT JOINT.
SO WAS THAT A MONEY ROAD TRIP,
OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OH, THAT'S CHEESE.
IT'S EDIBLE NAPKINS.
THESE GUYS ARE INCREDIBLE!