HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(man) PORK BURRITO.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHAT ARE YOU
ENJOYING, SIR?
SOMETHIN' FROM EVERYWHERE.
GARLIC CHICKEN KEBAB.
ITALIAN BEEF PIZZA.
PERNIL AREPAS.
ITALIAN IN CHICAGO...
I GOT A LARGE SAUSAGE, HALF
PEPPER AND ONION COMING OUT.
BUT THIS JOINT
IS DOING THIN CRUST...
LOOK HOW THIN THAT IS.
IN A THICK CRUST TOWN.
THE DEEP-DISH,
THAT'S FOR THOSE NORTH SIDE
PEOPLE UP AT WRIGLEY FIELD.
WHOA.
IN MINNEAPOLIS, HOME COOKING
LEBANESE STYLE...
DEFINITELY FRESH.
AND THERE'S JUST
SO MUCH TO CHOOSE FROM.
THE WAY MOM WAS DOING IT
35 YEARS AGO.
IT TASTES JUST AS GOOD AS
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
THE MEAT IS TENDER,
ALWAYS JUICY.
THAT'S NICE
AND BRIGHT AND FRESH.
LET THE MEAT
SHINE THROUGH.
MMM.
AND A CONNECTICUT STOREFRONT,
DOING VENEZUELAN BEACH FOOD...
THE TASTE IS OUTSTANDING.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS.
FROM A TRAINED CHEF...
I LOVE IT.
WHO PACKED UP, FLEW SOUTH
AND BROUGHT BACK THE SECRET
OF SOMETHING CALLED AN AREPA.
I LOVE YOUR SHAPE-A
OF YOUR AREPA.
LOOK AT THAT THING. MMM.
TING TANG WALLA WALLA BING BANG.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
WHEN YOU THINK CHICAGO,
YOU PROBABLY THINK
THAT THICK CRUST,
DEEP-DISH PIZZA.
SO YOU GOTTA STOP
AND TAKE A LOOK WHEN YOU FIND
A PIZZA JOINT IN CHICAGO
THAT'S DOING THE EXACT OPPOSITE.
AT VITO & NICK'S,
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN PILING IN
FOR THEIR THIN CRUST PIZZA
FOR OVER 60 YEARS.
IT'S REALLY CRISPY CRUST.
(Guy)LOOK HOW
THIN THAT IS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WITH A THICK CRUST PIZZA
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE BREAD.
OKAY, TELL ME NOW.
IF I WANT TO EAT BREAD,
I WILL EAT BREAD.
BUT AS ROSE GEORGE
WILL TELL YOU...
GOOD FOR YOU, GOOD FOR YOU.
IF YOU WANT TO EAT PIZZA...
HOW ARE YOU TONIGHT?
IT'S GONNA BE THE WAY HER
FAMILY'S DONE IT SINCE 1946.
DEEP-DISH, THAT'S FOR
THOSE NORTH SIDE PEOPLE
UP AT WRIGLEY FIELD.
WHOA.
THE CRUST
IS OUTSTANDING.
MY GRANDMOTHER
STARTED THIS.
SHE PERFECTED THE DOUGH
AND EVERYTHING.
AND YOU'RE USING
THE SAME RECIPE NOW?
ABSOLUTELY.
BON APPéTIT.
SO THIS IS WHERE
THE DOUGH MAGIC HAPPENS?
YES.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
THE FLOUR, ONE AND A HALF BAGS.
SHAKE A LITTLE BIT.
YOU GOT IT.
SOME SALT, SOME YEAST,
LITTLE BIT OF MILK.
IS A LITTLE BIT A GALLON?
NO. A LITTLE BIT
IS ABOUT 1/2 A GALLON.
NOTHING LIKE
MEASURING IT, MAYBE.
NO.
WE'RE NOW GONNA PUT
SOME WATER IN HERE.
STAND BACK.
I'M TRYING TO.
IT'LL MIX FIVE,
SIX MINUTES.
JUST TILL IT'S MIXED?
YEAH, JUST TILL MIXED.
I NEED TO ADD SOME WATER,
AND WHEN IT STARTS CREEPING UP
ON THIS HOOK, IT'S PRETTY WELL
FINISHED MIXING.
PULL IT OUT,
AND I'LL JUST COVER IT
AND THEN SET IT OFF
TO THE SIDE.
AND IT SITS OVER HERE.
SO THIS WILL SIT HERE
FOR HOW LONG?
TILL TOMORROW.
ONCE IT STARTS RAISING, EVERY
20 MINUTES TO HALF AN HOUR,
YOU CAN KEEP COMING IN HERE
AND PUNCHING IT DOWN.
DUMP IT ON
THE COUNTER.
BECAUSE OF THE AMOUNT
OF FLOUR AND WHAT I THINK
SHE'S GONNA DO TO ME,
I'M PUTTING ON THE APRON.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
GOOD JOB.
DO I NEED TO DE-BLING?
OH, YOU'RE WEARING YOUR BLING.
NO, I GOT MY BLINGS ON.
I HAVE MY BLINGS ON.
TEAR A PIECE OFF.
A LITTLE FLOUR ON THERE.
LIKE THIS.
ROLL IT INTO ITSELF.
YEAH, ROLL IT IN AND TIGHTEN IT.
MAKE IT TIGHT.
NICE AND SMOOTH LIKE
A BABY'S BOTTOM.
YEP.
AH, THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S OKAY?
IT'S OKAY.
I THOUGHT IT WAS
A PRETTY GOOD ONE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE A COUPLE.
YOU JUST WORK 'EM OUT TILL
THEY'RE MORE MANAGEABLE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA RUN 'EM
THROUGH THE FEEDER.
NOW I'M GONNA SEND IT
THROUGH THE NEXT ONE.
SO IT GOES THROUGH TWICE
ON THE BOTTOM?
NOW I'M GONNA SHOW YOU--
WE'RE GONNA PUT A BIT HERE.
DO YOU GO ALL THE WAY
TO THE EDGE?
ALL THE WAY TO THE EDGE.
THEY BURN.
THEY BURN IF YOU DON'T HAVE
SAUCE GLOPPING OFF OF THEM?
SURE THEY DO.
YOU WANT TO TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF CHEESE AND PUT A BASE ON IT.
AND THEN JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
FRESHEST INGREDIENTS
ACROSS THE BOARD.
PEPPERONI'S NOT OVERCOOKED.
NICE AND SOFT.
HOUSE SPECIAL.
SAUSAGE, ONION,
GREEN PEPPER, MUSHROOMS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND GET THIS ONE.
ITALIAN BEEF PIZZA.
YOU HEARD HER.
IT'S AMAZING.
THEY'RE PUTTING
A CHICAGO SPECIALTY,
ITALIAN BEEF, ON THE PIZZA,
AND THE BEEF'S HOMEMADE,
ROSE'S WAY.
THIS IS ROAST BEEF.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO WITH
ALL THESE TRIMMINGS OVER HERE?
I THROW NOTHING OUT. I'M GOING
TO GRIND THESE TRIMMINGS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SEASON THIS?
WELL, AFTER I
FLATTEN IT DOWN.
OKAY.
NOW I'M GONNA
TAKE SALT,
USE A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER
AND NOW GRANULATED GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA PUT OUR BEEF
ON TOP OF THE TRIMMINGS.
THEY WILL BE USED FOR THE BASE,
THEN I MAKE MY AU JUS WITH IT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN MAKING THIS?
LOTS OF YEARS.
NOW WE HAVE SOME MORE SALT,
LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
GRANULATED ONION,
NOT A LOT,
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
NO, JUST 1/2 A CUP.
AND GENEROUSLY NOW WITH
OUR GRANULATED GARLIC.
GARLIC, YES.
I LIKE THIS.
EVERYBODY ON THE MOUNTAIN.
SOME BASIL, OREGANO,
AND TO GIVE IT
EXTRA FLAVOR,
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
OLIVE OIL ON THE TOP.
THIS IS AN ADVENTURE
IN COOKING.
NOW I TAKE ALL THE TRIMMINGS.
YOU WANT TO TUCK 'EM IN.
I LOVE THIS.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA SLOW-ROAST FOR?
FOR A GOOD EIGHT HOURS.
SO WE'RE LOOKING FOR
A MEDIUM RARE IN HERE?
OH, AND IT WILL BE.
OH, LOOK AT THAT. IS THAT
PICTURE PERFECT OR WHAT?
NOW WE THROW IT UP
AND SLICE IT?
YES, WE DO.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU COULDN'T GET A BETTER
MEDIUM RARE THAN THAT.
SLOW IT DOWN.
I CAN'T EAT IT THIS FAST.
AND WHAT'RE WE GONNA DO
WITH THIS? PUT IT ON PIZZA?
I CAN'T EVEN SEE
THE PIZZA ANYMORE.
AND JUST PUT A LITTLE BIT
MORE CHEESE ON THE TOP
TO HOLD IT TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
THAT LOOKS LIKE A MANHOLE COVER
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
(laughs)
THAT LOOKS KILLER.
MMM.
THAT'S IT. ANYBODY THAT
WOULD COME TO CHICAGO
AND NOT COME HERE AND TRY THIS
SHOULD BE ARRESTED.
I'M MOVING IN.
GOOD.
IT REMINDS ME OF
AN ITALIAN BEEF SANDWICH
BUT ON THE PIZZA,
SO IT'S GREAT.
IT MAKES US HAPPY EVERY TIME WE
LEAVE HERE. IT'S A GREAT MEAL.
MMM.
I LIKE EVERYTHING
THEY HAVE HERE.
LARGE SAUSAGE.
HOW ABOUT IT?
AND THE JOINT'S SO BUSY,
THEY'RE MAKING MORE THAN
60 PIES AN HOUR.
A PIZZA SHOULD TAKE
A MINUTE FROM THE TIME
THAT NICKY GETS IT...
CUTS IT, SAUCES IT
AND SENDS IT FOR TOPPINGS.
TILL THE TIME THAT
I PUT OREGANO ON IT.
I GOT A LARGE SAUSAGE, HALF
PEPPER AND ONION COMING OUT.
GOT A LARGE CHEESE COMING OUT.
WATCH, WATCH, WATCH,
WATCH, WATCH.
THROWIN' THE BOARD AT HIM THING,
WHERE DID THAT COME FROM?
BEEN DOING IT FOR YEARS.
I THROW THE BOARD BACK TO NICKY,
NICKY CATCHES THE BOARD.
GRAB A PIZZA,
THROW IT IN THE OVEN
AND THE BOARD GOES BACK.
YOU'RE WORKING
A 10-HOUR SHIFT,
YOU TRY NOT TO WALK
AS MUCH AS YOU CAN.
AND THERE'S A CLOUD OF DUST
THAT COMES WITH IT.
(laughs) YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S THE WAY WE'VE
ALWAYS DONE IT.
HOWEVER YOU GET IT.
(man) WE'VE GOT
THE BREAKFAST PIZZA.
IT'S BREAKFAST PIZZA,
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE IT FOR
BREAKFAST, HAVE IT FOR DINNER.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE NOW?
EGG PIZZA.
WE NEED SOME CHEESE
ON HERE.
MAKE FIVE WELLS.
OH, WE'RE PUTTING 'EM
ON RAW.
AND YOU WANT TO START
FROM THE OUTSIDE,
PULL THE WHITES
TO THE CENTER,
OTHERWISE THEY'RE
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THERE'S A SCIENCE AND AN ART
TO HOW TO DO IT
AND WHERE TO DRAG THE YOLK.
A LITTLE BIT OF OREGANO.
NOW WE PUT OUR SECRET INGREDIENT
ON HERE SO IT DOESN'T DRY.
HALF CORN OIL, HALF WATER.
CRISPY PEPPERONI.
YOU'RE GONNA CRUMPLE THIS...
NICE.
AND SPRINKLE IT
ON TOP OF THE EGGS.
HIDE THAT ONE, HIDE THAT ONE.
THERE WE GO. CAN'T EVEN TELL
THERE'S EGGS ON THERE.
I'M EXCITED.
IT'S ABOUT READY
TO COME OUT.
DON'T QUIBBLE. TRY IT BEFORE
YOU SAY, "I DON'T LIKE IT."
I'M NOT SAYING
I DON'T LIKE IT.
OH, SHE WANTS YOU.
THAT WAS AWESOME.
I SAW THAT.
I'LL TELL YOU THIS,
IF YOU'RE NOT A BIG EGG FAN,
THE ONLY WAY TO EAT EGGS IS
TO SAY I WANT IT ON A PIZZA
WITH THIN CRUST
FROM VITO & NICK'S
COVERED IN FRIED PEPPERONI,
'CAUSE I'LL EAT IT THAT WAY.
THE CREAMINESS OF THE CHEESE
AND THE LITTLE BIT OF SPICINESS
OF THE PEPPERONI, DELICIOUS.
I COULD EAT THIS PIZZA
FOR EVERY MEAL. THIS IS SO GOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
THIS IS THE STANDARD BY
WHICH ALL OTHERS ARE MEASURED.
(Guy) THIS IS A PIZZERIA.
THIS IS A COME-TO FAMILY JOINT.
THIS ISN'T JUST COMING
AND GETTING A PIE.
THIS IS AN EVENT...
GIVE ME 30 SECONDS.
AND YOU'RE CRAZY.
(both laughing)
UP NEXT...
DEFINITELY FRESH.
MIDDLE EASTERN
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
SO GOOD.
AND ONE THOSE SPECIALS THEY'RE
ALWAYS DARING ME TO TRY.
HAVING TROUBLE.
NO. OBVIOUSLY, IT WAS
TEARS OF JOY.
HERE ON TRIPLE "D," WE'RE ALL
ABOUT CLASSIC AMERICAN JOINTS.
AND THE GREAT THIS IS,
THE WAY WE EAT TODAY,
WELL, THAT MEANS
FROM EVERYWHERE--
CHINESE, MEXICAN, ITALIAN,
YOU NAME IT.
WELL, TODAY WE'RE ON UNIVERSITY
AVENUE IN MINNEAPOLIS,
AND WE'RE GONNA GO CHECK OUT
SOME HOMEMADE LEBANESE.
SO GOOD.
IS THIS LEGIT LEBANESE?
DEFINITELY.
EVERYTHING'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE BEST TABBOULEH
IN THE TWIN CITIES.
YOU'RE NO FOOL-Y WHEN YOU'RE
MAKING THE TABBOULEH.
GARLIC CHICKEN KEBAB.
THE SPINACH PIE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
GRAPE LEAVES FILLED
WITH LAMB AND RICE.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT TASTES JUST
AS GOOD AS MY MOTHER
AND MY GRANDMOTHER
USED TO MAKE.
AND RON AWAIJANE'S GRANDMOTHER.
THESE ARE RECIPES THAT MY MOTHER
LEARNED FROM HER MOTHER...
AND STARTED COOKING FOR
THE WHOLE NEIGHBORHOOD IN 1973.
HOW DO WE THIS SHISH KEBAB?
THESE DAYS...
13 IS UP.
RON'S STILL USING
THE SAME FAMILY RECIPE.
(woman) THE MEAT PIES.
(man) HOLY COW.
I'M CARRYING ON
THE FAMILY TRADITION...
LIKE THIS MIDDLE EASTERN
CLASSIC, LAMB SHISH KEBAB.
SHISH KEBAB'S READY.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE
SO MUCH ABOUT IT?
I LOVE THE LAMB.
UNBELIEVABLE. IT REALLY IS.
THE MEAT IS TENDER,
ALWAYS JUICY...
AND HAND-CUT.
WHAT I DO, WE JUST START
WITH THE WHOLE LEG
AND DISASSEMBLE.
BOY, YOU REALLY KNOW YOUR--
I MEAN, LOOK AT THIS.
OH, YEAH.
YOUR GETTING THE OPTIMUM
PORTIONS OF THE LAMB,
CLEANING THEM UP
AND THEN MAKING THE BEST CUBES
THAT YOU CAN GET
FOR THE KEBAB.
EXACTLY.
DUDE KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS KIND OF PLACE THAT I
WOULD WANT TO GET A KEBAB FROM.
THIS IS THE WAY I LIKE IT.
SO THAT'S ENOUGH TO GET
A COUPLE OF KEBABS STARTED?
YEP.
FOUR PIECES, ZUCCHINI,
ONION NOW.
SO IT'S A FOUR,
DOUBLE UP,
THREE, DOUBLE UP.
AND THEN YOU PUT THREE
ON TOP OF THAT.
READY FOR COOKING.
NICE, HOT CHARBROIL.
WE'RE GONNA LET 'EM SEAR
ON THE ONE SIDE, FLIP 'EM OVER
AND THEN BASTE 'EM...
WITH A HOMEMADE SAUCE OF
GARLIC, SALT, BUTTER AND OIL...
ALL RAN THROUGH
A BLENDER.
THAT TASTES GREAT.
SO THIS TAKES?
ABOUT FIVE,
SIX MINUTES.
IDEALLY, THEY SHOULD
BE PINK, NOT WELL DONE.
SO THIS WILL GET
SERVED WITH WHAT?
PLATED WITH RICE
AND EAT IT WITH THE BREAD,
LEBANESE FLATBREAD.
WE'RE READY.
YOU TAKE A PIECE OF BREAD,
PULL IT OFF,
SPLIT IT OPEN SO YOU'RE NOT
GETTING ALL BREAD.
YEAH.
GRAB A PIECE...
EDIBLE NAPKIN.
MMM. THAT'S AWESOME.
NICE AND MEDIUM RARE.
THAT'S THE WAY TO EAT IT.
THAT'S BRIGHT
AND NICE AND FRESH.
THAT'S GREAT LAMB.
LET THE MEAT SHINE THROUGH.
THAT'S ON POINT, MAN.
I LIKE THE WAY IT'S JUST GRILLED
TO HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF TEXTURE ON THE OUTSIDE,
THEN THE INSIDE IS VERY TENDER.
IT'S JUST REALLY LIKE
A NICE SUBTLE FLAVOR.
IT JUST TASTES GREAT.
NEVER REALLY HAD LAMB BEFORE,
AND NOW I LOVE IT.
IT'S MY FIRST TIME HERE,
AND I'LL BE BACK.
HOW MANY PEOPLE DO YOU THINK
YOU INTRODUCED
LEBANESE FOOD TO
FOR THE FIRST TIME?
WE INTRODUCED THE WHOLE CITY
TO LEBANESE FOOD, I THINK.
EVERYTHING FROM SPINACH PIE...
DEFINITELY FRESH.
TO LENTILS AND RICE,
STUFFED ZUCCHINI,
A CRACKED WHEAT SALAD
CALLED TABBOULEH...
JUST OUTSTANDING.
TO SOMETHING CALLED KIBBE.
(woman) KIBBE COMBINATION.
GROUND BEEF MIXED
WITH BULGUR WHEAT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
YOU CAN HAVE IT RAW,
OR YOU CAN HAVE IT BAKED
WITH A FILLING
OF GROUND LAMB.
THE RAW KIBBE, KIND OF
THE LEBANESE VERSION
OF STEAK TARTARE.
THE BAKED KIBBE.
IT'S A DIFFERENT FLAVOR
THAN THE RAW. IT'S DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING IS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT BUT REALLY GOOD.
AND THEN THERE'S
REALLY DIFFERENT.
THIS IS LAMB'S TONGUE...
BOILED AND SERVED
WITH AN HERB VINAIGRETTE.
I AM LOOKING FORWARD
TO HAVING SOME TONGUE.
THEY'RE APPETIZING.
FIRST THING THAT CAME
TO MY MIND. APPETIZING.
WE'LL PUT IT ON THE BOARD,
AND IF ANYBODY
FEELS ADVENTUROUS
THEY'LL ORDER IT.
(whistles)
WOW, THOSE LOOK
INTERESTING.
OKAY! HERE WE GO.
HAVING TROUBLE?
NO.
OBVIOUSLY, IT WAS
TEARS OF JOY.
IT'S PROBABLY THE MOST TENDER
PIECE OF THE ANIMAL
I'VE EVER EATEN.
THIS IS LIKE FILLET.
EXACTLY.
I DIG IT. YEAH, I MEAN, I DON'T
KNOW--WHAT I'M TRYING TO SAY,
IT'S JUST RIGHT ON THE TIP
OF MY TONGUE.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD IT BEFORE?
NO, I HAVEN'T.
THAT'S TENDER.
I'M SURPRISED,
BUT IT IS VERY GOOD.
THE FOOD IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
AND THERE'S JUST
SO MUCH TO CHOOSE FROM.
WHAT'RE YOU ENJOYING SIR?
THIS IS A MEAT PIE.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
HE MAKES IT FRESH.
RIGHT FROM GRANDMA'S RECIPE.
LET'S GET IT ON.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR. I'LL BE OVER
HERE 'CAUSE I HAVE BLACK ON.
YEAST, SUGAR, SALT.
WE'RE GONNA DISSOLVE THIS.
THEN INTO THE FLOUR?
YES.
OKAY, SO YOU'LL LET THIS RUN
FOR FIVE MINUTES?
APPROXIMATELY. UNTIL I GET
A NICE, SMOOTH BALL.
DONE AND GOOD, HUH?
LET IT SIT FOR A WHILE.
DUST THE TABLE A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA DUST OUR MACHINE UP.
WHEN MY MA USED TO BAKE,
THEY DID IT ALL BY HAND...
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
OH, IT'S BROUGHT TO YOU
BY CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG.
ONE MORE TIME.
SO YOUR MOM
TAUGHT YOU ALL THIS?
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT.
HANDY-DANDY
COOKIE CUTTER...
(whistles)
THAT THE OLD LEBANESE HANDYMAN
MADE FOR MY MA.
SO THIS, WE'RE
GONNA LOAD UP.
YEP.
JUST GONNA PUT A TABLESPOON
OR SO OF THE...
MEAT PIE FILLING.
GONNA START WITH SOME
GROUND LAMB, GROUND BEEF.
BROWN UP.
WE'RE GONNA DRAIN THIS OFF.
SO THAT DRAINS
THE FAT OUT OF IT.
DOWN WITH SOME ONIONS.
ALL THOSE ONIONS?
YEP.
WOW.
THEY'RE GONNA
SHRINK DOWN TO NOTHING.
NOW WHAT'RE WE DOING HERE?
WE'RE GONNA BROWN
SOME PINE NUTS.
GIVE IT A TOSS.
JUST A LITTLE OIL
JUST TO COAT 'EM.
GONNA DUMP THE MEAT THAT'S
BEEN DRAINING INTO A BOWL.
NOW THE PINE NUTS.
WOW, THAT'S FRAGRANT.
LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
SALT, PEPPER,
NUTMEG, JUST A TOUCH,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF CINNAMON.
NOW THE ONION.
MMM. DEFINITELY PICK UP
THE CINNAMON AND NUTMEG.
NOW WE START TO PUT IT
INTO THE DOUGH.
EXACTLY.
FANTASTIC.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA PUT
A TABLESPOON OR SO.
GATHER IT IN THE MIDDLE ON TOP,
PINCH IT OFF.
MAKIN' A WONTON...
SAME, JUST DIFFERENT.
MY MA WOULD BE
PROUD OF YOU.
REALLY? I'M NOT DOING
TOO BAD, HUH?
NO, IT'S PERFECT.
AND WE'LL BAKE IT
FOR HOW LONG?
IT'LL TAKE ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
AND THEY COME OUT
GOLDEN BROWN.
WOW.
SO JUST EAT 'EM AS IS?
JUST LIKE THAT.
MMM. GREAT FLAVOR.
GREAT DOUGH.
I GET SWEET AND SOUR.
LEMON JUICE.
LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
LITTLE CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT OF
SPICINESS TO IT.
YOU CAN TELL I DIDN'T LIKE IT.
ALL I LEFT WERE THE CORNERS.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
NOT BAD, HUH?
I LIKE THE SPICES A LOT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
THEY JUST HAVE
REALLY GREAT FOOD.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT DAY OF
THE WEEK YOU'RE COMING,
ALWAYS GOOD FOOD.
STUFFED ZUCCHINI.
HAVEN'T FOUND
ANOTHER RESTAURANT
THAT HAS LEBANESE
FOOD LIKE THIS.
WE'RE BASICALLY A THROWBACK.
IT'S TRADITION.
I LIKE TRADITION,
SO I KEEP COMING.
PEOPLE ENJOY
WHAT WE MAKE.
IT'S SOMETHING
THAT MAKES PEOPLE HAPPY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
I KNOW YOU NEED HELP
WITH THAT. CALL ME.
(laughter)
NEXT STOP...
TWO CHICKEN EMPANADAS
WITH A FAJITA.
CONNECTICUT...
VENEZUELAN BEACH FOOD.
THE TASTE IS OUTSTANDING.
TO GRAB A SANDWICH,
VENEZUELAN STYLE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA STUFF IT.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
GETTING THE TING?
TING TANG
WALLA WALLA BING BANG.
YOU KNOW WHAT KIND OF JOINTS
WE'RE LOOKING FOR
ON TRIPLE "D", RIGHT?
CRAZY PLACES,
LIKE THIS ONE HERE
IN CONNECTICUT--
A VENEZUELAN RESTAURANT.
NOW HERE'S THE KICKER.
THE DUDE THAT OWNS IT, WHEN HE
WANTED TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT VENEZUELAN COOKING,
HE BOUNCED OUT OF THE U.S.,
CRUISED DOWN TO VENEZUELA,
STARTED AS A DISHWASHER
IN A RESTAURANT,
LEARNED A BUNCH OF STUFF,
CAME BACK TO THE U.S. AND OPENED
UP THIS, VALENCIA LUNCHERIA.
TWO CHICKEN EMPANADAS
WITH A FAJITA.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS.
I LOVE IT.
IT REMINDS ME OF THE LATIN
COUNTRY I LIVED IN.
INTERESTING, ETHNIC, FUN.
VENEZUELAN BEACH FOOD.
I PARTICULARLY LOVE
THE AREPAS.
I HAD MY FIRST AREPA
IN MANHATTAN.
AND YOU SAID, W-W-WAIT,
THERE'S GOTTA BE MORE OF THIS.
CONNECTICUT'S
GOTTA HAVE IT.
IT IS A KIND OF SANDWICH
MADE WITH A VENEZUELAN DOUGH
AND FILLED WITH
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
THE COCONUT SHRIMP AREPA.
THE BRIE AND MANGO,
AMAZING.
FRESH MOZZARELLA
AND CHORIZO.
THE TASTE
IS OUTSTANDING.
THAT'S 'CAUSE TRAINED CHEF
MICHAEL YOUNG...
(Michael) WAITING ON COCO AREPA.
HEADED TO VENEZUELA
TO LEARN HOW TO MAKE 'EM.
OKAY, PICK UP.
I KNEW THAT THIS WOULD BE
SOMETHING NEW TO CONNECTICUT,
AND AMERICANS WOULD LOVE IT.
UNO AREPA...
WHAT'RE YOU ENJOYING TODAY?
PERNIL AREPAS.
PERNIL.
EXACTLY.
WHAT IS PERNIL?
PERNIL IS THE PORK SHOULDER
IN VENEZUELA.
WHAT WE CALL THE PORK BUTT.
WE'RE GONNA BRINE
THE PERNIL.
WATER, WHITE VINEGAR--
THAT TO ME KIND OF FALLS
INTO THAT CUBAN IDEA.
A LOT OF VINEGAR
USED IN THAT.
DELICIOUS. A MOJO.
A MOJO.
SO SOME OF THAT--
YEAH, A MOJO, EXACTLY.
2 CUPS OF SUGAR,
KOSHER SALT, EQUAL PARTS,
BAY LEAVES, DRIED ROSEMARY.
IS ROSEMARY BIG
IN VENEZUELAN FOOD?
NO, THAT'S MY INFLUENCE.
NOW THE CHIPOTLE SAUCE,
THE ONE WE MAKE HERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE PORK
SHOULDER AND POP IT IN.
AND THEN I'M GONNA BRINE
THE PORK IN THERE FOR 72 HOURS.
REALLY? THAT LONG?
YES. IT'S ALMOST PICKLED.
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK HOW MUCH
IT SETTLED DOWN AND ABSORBED.
A LITTLE ADOBO--
CUMIN, GARLIC, ONION POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER, WHITE PEPPER--
EVENLY DISTRIBUTED
AND QUITE GENEROUSLY.
GUASACACA.
OH, THAT'S AWESOME.
WHAT IS THAT?
BASICALLY, A PUREED COLD
VEGETABLE SAUCE.
THEY DRINK IT
BY THE CUP HERE.
DUDE, I WOULD.
PUT A LITTLE WATER IN THE PAN
SO IT DOESN'T BURN.
YEAH.
NOW HOW LONG WILL WE COOK IT?
THREE HOURS COVERED,
THREE HOURS NOT COVERED.
SO YOU GET NICE CRUST GOING.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
WHERE HAS THIS
BEEN ALL MY LIFE?
RIGHT HERE IN NORWALK.
OKAY, SO WE SHRED SOME OF THIS
AND THEN POP IT INTO AN AREPA.
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE MASA FOR THE AREPAS.
WE START WITH WATER,
KOSHER SALT,
SOME BLACK PEPPER--
COARSELY GROUND,
PRECOOKED CORNMEAL--
COMING STRAIGHT FROM THERE.
AND THAT WITH
THE HAND WHISK.
LOOKS LIKE HE'S DOING AN ANGRY
MONSTER STIR. (growls)
CHEF, CAN YOU HOLD
THE BOWL? THANK YOU.
HOLD THE BOWL OR THAT?
THE BOWL, CHEF. A LITTLE
FASTER NEXT TIME, OKAY?
YES. NO. THANK YOU.
I CAN GET FOOT RIGHT IN THERE
AND STIR THAT UP WITH YOU, TOO.
FROM STANDING THERE?
I DOUBT IT.
YOU SHOULD SEE MY YOGA.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR A 5-INCH CIRCLE.
HOW'RE WE LOOKING?
PRETTY GOOD, CHEF.
VENEZUELANS ONLY EAT THEM
ON THE GRIDDLE,
BUT HERE IN THE STATES WE DO
THEM ALMOST THE OPPOSITE.
SO WE'RE GONNA DEEP-FRY THESE?
PUT IT ON TOP
SO THEY DON'T SWIM.
STAY IN YOUR CAGE.
THREE AND A HALF
MINUTES LATER.
I LOVE YOUR SHAPE-A
OF YOUR AREPA.
GRAZIE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
STUFF IT WITH...
PERNIL.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
MMM.
IT HAS GREAT FLAVOR, SO MOIST.
THE PORK IS SO TENDER.
THE AREPA HAS JUST SUCH
GREAT TEXTURE TO IT.
THAT'S CAPITAL "T"
TASTY RIGHT THERE, BRO.
YOU WOULD
SO LOVE THIS. MMM.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
A LITTLE OUT OF THE ORDINARY
IN FAIRFIELD COUNTY.
(Michael) PERNIL AREPA,
PORK BURRITO.
THEY HAVE A HUGE SELECTION
OF DIFFERENT DISHES.
ROAST CHICKEN WITH
GARLIC AND JALAPEÑO.
EMPANADAS ARE FANTASTIC.
YEAH, THE CLASSIC
SOUTH AMERICAN PASTRY,
BUT MICHAEL'S STUFFING 'EM
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
14 DIFFERENT ONES.
WHAT?
SPINACH AND CHEESE EMPANADA.
DOMINO EMPANADA, WHICH IS
BLACK BEAN AND CHEESE.
WE DO SOME
SWEET ONES, TOO.
AN EMPANADA THAT'S GOT
NUTELLA AND CREAM CHEESE
INSIDE OF IT. THAT IS SO GOOD.
WHAT'S THIS BAD BOY?
CHICKEN EMPANADA.
CHICKEN MECHADA IN VENEZUELA.
MECHADA MEANS SHREDDED.
START WITH OLIVE OIL,
ONIONS.
A LITTLE GARLIC?
JUST A LITTLE, YEAH.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
SOME GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
SOME RED BELL PEPPERS.
YEP. IT'S NOT A SPICY CHICKEN.
IT'S NICE AND FLAVORFUL.
CHICKEN BREAST NOW.
THE CHICKEN'S ALREADY COOKED.
YOU JUST REALLY WANT TO WET IT.
CANNED PLUM TOMATOES. ONCE
THE TOMATOES START TO HEAT UP,
YOU GO IN WITH
THE WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
THAT GIVES IT
A LITTLE TAMARINDO TING.
TAMARINDO TING. I'VE NEVER
HEARD IT DESCRIBED THAT WAY.
SALT AND PEPPER,
DRY OREGANO, CILANTRO.
DID YOU SAY CI-LANTRO?
HOW DO YOU SAY IT?
CI-LAANTRO.
YOU CAN REMOVE THE LONG ISLAND
FROM THE GUY,
BUT YOU CAN'T REMOVE
THE LONG ISLAND FROM THE GUY.
AND OUR CHIPOTLE SAUCE.
SO THIS IS DONE.
WE LET THIS COOL, AND NOW WE'RE
GONNA MAKE THE EMPANADAS.
YES.
SO YOU ROLL 'EM ALL OUT.
YOU BRING THE BOWL DOWN,
AND YOU CUT OUT YOUR DISK.
YES.
BROTHER, THAT IS
SOME EMPANADA DOUGH.
THIS IS OUR
CHICKEN MECHADA.
CHICKEN GENEROUS.
FOLD, CRIMP IT
NICE AND TIGHT.
THREE FINGERS,
HOLD DOWN, FLIP,
HOLD DOWN, FLIP.
THAT'S THE BRAIDED METHOD.
SEE, WE DO IT
TUG AND PULL.
TUG AND PULL?
POP IT IN THE FRYER.
PUT THE BASKET
RIGHT ON TOP.
ABOUT THREE AND A HALF
MINUTES LATER, COMES OUT.
MORE SOUP, PLEASE.
EVERYTHING IN THIS,
HANDMADE.
MMM. THERE'S NO
FOOLING AROUND WITH THIS.
MMM. THE TENDER CHICKEN
SHREDDING APART.
THE EMPANADA DOUGH IS SO
NICE AND FLAKY AND CRUSTY. OHH.
GETTING THE TING?
I'M GETTING THE TANG. TING TANG
WALLA WALLA BING BANG.
CAN'T YOU GUYS DO SOMETHING
RIGHT NOW?
I'M JUST STARTING TO EAT. DUDE,
THAT'S--THAT IS AWESOME.
THANKS, CHEF.
ROCKIN'.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
THE FOOD IS
ALWAYS EXCELLENT.
REALLY IMAGINATIVE.
LIKE MUSSELS IN
A CHORIZO CREAM SAUCE...
THEY'RE AWESOME.
BANANA LEAF-WRAPPED MAHIMAHI
WITH A PINEAPPLE SAUCE...
FLAVORS ARE VERY DIFFERENT
FROM OTHER TYPES OF FOOD.
AND MICHAEL'S TAKE ON A SOUTH
AMERICAN SEAFOOD CLASSIC.
YOU GOTTA COME BACK.
THIS IS GONNA BE MONEY.
I NEED TWO CHICKEN EMPANADAS,
ONE BEEF, ONE CUBAN.
AT VALENCIA LUNCHERIA
IN NORWALK, CONNECTICUT...
FAJITAS ALL SET.
OWNER MICHAEL YOUNG IS SERVING
UP REAL DEAL BEACH FOOD
THE WAY HE LEARNED IT
IN VENEZUELA.
CHICKEN EMPANADA.
AND PEOPLE LOVE IT
DON'T THEY?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S UNUSUAL. IT'S A CUISINE
THAT I LIKE.
THE FOOD IS
VERY ECLECTIC.
AND WORTH A LEARNING CURVE.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT THIS IS,
BUT IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S CALLED A TOSTONE. YOU TAKE
A PLANTAIN WHEN THEY'RE GREEN,
CUT SLICES OUT OF 'EM,
YOU FRY 'EM PARTIALLY,
THEN YOU PRESS 'EM
AND YOU SMASH 'EM DOWN,
THEN YOU FRY 'EM AGAIN. AND IT'S
KIND OF LIKE THE TORTILLA
IN VENEZUELAN FOOD
OR CUBAN FOOD.
AND MICHAEL'S MAKING 'EM
FRESH EVERY DAY
TO GO WITH HIS TAKE
ON A SEAFOOD CLASSIC.
IT'S THE HOUSE SEVICHE,
AND I DO IT
WITH SHRIMP AND SCALLOPS,
AND I DO BLANCH THEM.
SO YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET
THE CRUNCH...
I DIG IT. I DIG IT.
SO JUST DOWN
AND OUT AND COOL.
TEN SECONDS, YES.
I TRY TO TELL PEOPLE
THIS SAME TOPIC,
BLANCH IT AND SHOCK IT.
TEN SECONDS.
BOOM BOOM.
AND ONTO A SHEET PAN,
QUICK COOL.
NOT HIS FIRST RODEO.
SHRIMP, SCALLOPS--
BAY SCALLOPS.
I USE A TRINITY
OF THE JUICES,
THREE LEMONS, THREE LIMES,
THREE ORANGES.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL--
IT ADDS A NICE RICHNESS
IN THE SEVICHE.
RIGHT.
OUR CHIPOTLE SAUCE,
THAT'S THE HEAT.
FRESH CILANTRO,
CHOPPED TOMATOES, FRESH,
RED BELL PEPPERS,
GREEN BELL PEPPERS...
I LOVE WHERE THIS IS GOING.
RED ONIONS, SALT AND PEPPER
AND SOME KETCHUP.
THE INTERNATIONAL ELIXIR.
ACTUALLY A SEVICHE THAT
YOU MIGHT FIND IN HONDURAS,
BECAUSE IT'S RED.
NOW HOW LONG WILL YOU
LET THIS MARINATE UP?
JUST ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
IT'S READY TO EAT NOW.
IT'S READY NOW.
WE CAN GO NOW, RIGHT?
TOSTONES.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE MAKING--
YOU'RE MAKING ME HUNGRY.
LET'S GO WITH THIS.
ALL RIGHT. SEVICHE.
YOU GET A LITTLE MUSIC
GOING IN THE BACKGROUND
AND LET ME HEAR SOME BIRDS AND
A LITTLE CRASHING OF THE OCEAN
AND I MIGHT BE THERE.
YOU'VE GOT YOUR FEET IN
THE SAND ALREADY, DON'T YOU?
SERIOUSLY, NO,
I-I'M FEELING IT.
MMM. THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THAT IS GREAT. OH,
PEOPLE GOTTA TRY THIS.
THE TOSTONES
ARE PERFECT.
DELICIOUS, FRESH,
HANDMADE.
IT'S AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVOR,
AND NOBODY IS TAKING
A SOLO RIGHT NOW. EXCELLENT.
MMM.
THE SEVICHE IS INCREDIBLE.
THE SHRIMP ARE
JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
YOU CANNOT GO WRONG
WITH THE FOOD. IT'S EXCELLENT.
I CAN ALWAYS GET SOMETHING
REALLY, REALLY, TASTY.
WE'RE SO HAPPY
TO HAVE THIS HERE.
HOW'D YOU HEAR
ABOUT THE PLACE?
WELL, WE NOTICED YOUR AWESOME-
LOOKING CAR OUTSIDE, SO...
YOU NOTICED THE "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES" CAMARO?
YEAH, I DID.
AND THAT'S WHY
YOU STOPPED?
YES. THAT'S A FANTASTIC CAR.
HUH? YOU SEE?
WORD GETS AROUND.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THROW ME THE THING.
WE'RE GONNA DO
IT AGAIN?
HEY!
GOOD JOB.
(laughs)