I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE, DEAR?
(Guy)
THIS TRIP...
THERE YOU GO.
(Guy)
JUST LIKE YESTERDAY.
YOU VERY MUCH FEEL LIKE
YOU STEPPED BACK IN TIME.
(Guy)
IN SAN DIEGO...
DELICIOUS HOME FOOD.
(Guy)
64 YEARS OF
OLD-TIME FAVORITES.
IT'S A HISTORIC LANDMARK.
SINCE FOREVER.
(Guy)
FROM CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE...
IT'S SUPER TENDER
REALLY GOOD CORNED BEEF.
(Guy)
TO CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
BETTER THAN MOTHER
USED TO MAKE.
THAT GUY IS NUMBER ONE.
(Guy)
IN CHICAGO...
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
WE LOVE JOEY.
(Guy)
A THIRD GENERATION ITALIAN.
IT'S A FAMILY PLACE.
(Guy)
WHERE THEY'RE USING GRANDMA'S
RECIPES...
TASTE LIKE HOMEMADE COOKING.
(Guy)
FROM THE '30s.
THE LEMON CHICKEN IS
THE BEST THING THEY SERVE.
IT'S A WONDERFUL DISH,
DELICIOUS.
(Guy)
AND IN ATLANTA...
TWO SCRAMBLED, HAM...
(Guy)
HALF A CENTURY
OF SOUTHERN COOKING.
CHICKEN BISCUIT.
BACON JELLY BISCUIT.
(Guy)
WHERE GRITS ARE A FOOD GROUP,
THERE'S COFFEE IN THE GRAVY,
AND...
SOY SAUCE, BROWN SUGAR,
PAPRIKA, COLA,
SOUNDS LIKE BREAKFAST
DOESN'T IT?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON,
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
SOMETHING I'VE ALWAYS SAID
SINCE WE STARTED "TRIPLE D,"
IS THATA CLASSIC DINER
ON THE EAST COAST
IS JUST LIKE A COFFEE SHOP
IN CALI,
YOU KNOW, WITHOUT
THE STAINLESS STEEL AND ALL.
YOU KNOW, IT'S ALWAYS ONE OF
THOSE PLACES YOU WANT TO GO TO,
GOOD FOOD, GOOD PRICES,
AND IT FEELS LIKE IT'S BEEN
THERE FOREVER.
LIKE THIS JOINT HERE IN
SAN DIEGO, HOB NOB HILL.
THEY OPENED THE DOORS
ON THIS PLACE BACK IN THE '40s.
THANK YOU.
CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE.
THIS IS MOTHER'S COOKING.
SIMPLE DELICIOUS, HOME FOOD.
IT'S A HISTORIC
LITTLE LANDMARK.
SINCE, I DON'T KNOW,
FOREVER.
IT NEVER CHANGES.
IF IT AIN'T BROKE
DON'T FIX IT.
(Guy)
AND IT AIN'T BROKE.
SO JEFF KACHA
AND HIS WIFE TANIA
ARE KEEPIN' IT JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
NOW THE PEOPLE THAT YOU
BOUGHT IT FROM...
THE ORIGINAL OWNERS,
THEY ASKED "IF I WERE
TO SELL IT TO YOU
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?"
AND I SAID, "NOTHING."
THAT'S A GOOD ATTITUDE,
MAN.
AND THAT'S WHY
HE CHOSE US TO BUY IT,
BECAUSE WE SAID WE
WOULDN'T CHANGE A THING.
(Guy)
NOT THE FRENCH TOAST,
NOT THE SHORT RIBS...
(Tania)
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
(Guy)
AND NOT THIS CHILDHOOD FAVORITE.
IT'S A COMFORT FOOD,
I LOVE THE FLAVORS.
WHEN I WAS A KID WE USED
TO PACK ON THE HORSES
UP IN THE MOUNTAINS.
WE WOULD BE COLD
AND MY DAD WOULD SAY,
"I'M GONNA MAKE SOMETHING
TO WARM YOU UP."
AND HE WOULD MAKE
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
AND IT WAS THE GREATEST
THING IN THE WORLD.
SO LET'S GET IT ON.
WE HAVE FOUR CHICKENS.
JUST THE WHOLE CHICKEN,
WE'RE NOT BREAKING THEM UP
OR ANYTHING.
NO, TOSS THEM IN THERE.
PUT IN SOME ONIONS
AND CELERY.
SOME CARROTS,
SEASONED SALT, WATER.
THIS GONNA KIND OF MAKE
OUR STOCK ALSO?
CORRECT.
ENOUGH TO COVER
THE CHICKEN.
WE SIMMER THIS
FOR?
TWO HOURS.
TAKE THE CHICKENS OUT,
THERE WE GO.
LET THIS COOL DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE ALL
THE CHICKEN OFF THE BONE.
DON'T USE THE SKIN
AND STRAIN THE STOCK.
LOOK AT THAT,
THAT'S GOLDEN NECTAR.
THAT'S CHICKEN GRAVY
GOODNESS, RIGHT?
SALT.
LITTLE CHICKEN BASE TO IT
TO FORTIFY THE FLAVOR
A LITTLE MORE.
SO HERE'S OUR BREW,
LET THAT TIGHTEN UP.
WHEN ARE WE GOING
TO MAKE THE DUMPLINGS?
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE THOSE DUMPLINGS
RIGHT NOW.
LET'S GO DUMPLIFY.
EGGS, VEGETABLE OIL,
BAKING POWDER...
SALT,
AND NOW FLOUR.
YOU WHISK ALL THAT UP.
SO THIS IS KIND OF
A WET DOUGH VERSUS
A KNEADED DOUGH?
CORRECT.
YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF MILK, ALL OF IT,
OR A LITTLE AT A TIME?
LITTLE AT A TIME.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA DROP IT
INTO THE GRAVY?
SCOOP IT OUT AND STEAM IT
IN A STEAMER.
WHOA, IT DOESN'T GO
THROUGH THE HOLE?
NO.
HOW LONG WILL THEY TAKE?
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
DUDE, I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THAT.
I'M EXCITED!!
LOOK AT THOSE
BAD BOYS.
OH, YOU ADD A LITTLE
DARK AND WHITE MEAT.
OH YEAH.
YOU GET OUT,
LOOK AT THAT.
WOW, IT'S JUST
MASSIVE FLAVOR.
TENDER CHICKEN.
THE DUMPLING
BEING DONE IN THE STEAM,
I MEAN, THE WHOLE
GIDDY-UP, BROTHER,
THIS IS ABOUT AS OLD-SCHOOL
AS IT GETS.
THAT SHOULD BE THE DEFINITION
OF CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
THIS IS JUST,
YOU'RE ON POINT, MAN.
IT'S A VERY HOMEMADE DISH.
BETTER THAN MOTHER
USED TO MAKE.
AND YOU CAN TELL IT WAS
DELICIOUS, BECAUSE IT'S GONE.
I THINK EVERYTHING IS
VERY, VERY GOOD.
IT'S JUST OLD SCHOOL.
(Guy)
AND HAS BEEN SINCE '44.
I HAVE SOME MUFFINS
FOR YOU THERE.
WE USUALLY COME HERE
FOR BREAKFAST.
I HAVE THE PANCAKES.
THE WALDORF SALAD, WHO DOES
WALDORF SALAD ANYMORE?
THE LAMB SHANK.
(Guy)
YEP, LIKE BACK IN THE '40s
WITH MINT JELLY.
IT JUST FALLS OFF THE BONE.
WANT ME TO PLATE ONE UP
FOR YOU?
NO, I WANT YOU
TO PLATE FOUR.
SERVED UP,
LOOK AT THAT THING.
THAT IS A MONSTER
SHANK.
LITTLE MASH ON THERE.
WOW, MAN.
WELL I GOTTA SAY SOMETHING ABOUT
THE WAY THEY WERE DOING THEM
BACK IN 1944,
THEY WERE KNOCKING THEM DEAD.
THANK YOU.
(Guy)
AND THEY STILL ARE.
WE HAVE REGULARS THAT HAVE BEEN
COMING HERE FOR A LONG TIME.
AND EVERYTHING'S GOOD?
WONDERFUL.
35, 40 YEARS.
THEY'LL SIT AT THE SAME TABLE,
SAME TIME.
WE HAVE STANDING RESERVATIONS
THREE DAYS A WEEK.
STANDING RESERVATIONS.
SO IF THEY EVER WANT
TO COME AND FIND YOU,
THEY KNOW WHERE
YOU'RE GONNA BE.
(Guy)
AND WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA EAT.
IT'S ONE OF THE STANDARDS
HERE.
THESE BIG OL' BRISKETS,
WE'RE NOT GOING TO TRIM THEM
OR ANYTHING,
BECAUSE YOU WANT FAT
AS FLAVOR.
SO NOW WE'RE GOING
TO MAKE THE BRINE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SALT.
WHOA!
GO AHEAD AND POUR IT
INTO OUR WHITE BUCKET.
WHEN DOES THE PICKLING
SPICE GET INVOLVED?
WE'RE GONNA THROW THAT   IN
RIGHT NOW.
SO YOU DUMP IN A COUPLE
OF CUPS OF THAT.
NOW HOW LONG WILL YOU
LET THIS BRINE?
THIS IS A SEVEN-DAY CURE.
SEVEN DAY, REALLY?
WE HAVE SEVEN OF THESE
BUCKETS GOING.
YOU MAKE ONE EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
SO AFTER THAT WE GO AHEAD
AND WEIGH THEM DOWN
WITH PLATES.
AND THE REASON YOU USE
THE PLATES IS SO
YOU GET THE PRESSURE
ALL AROUND,
AS OPPOSED TO JUST ONE,
BECAUSE ONE WILL BUBBLE UP.
AND THAT'S HOW WE'LL
LEAVE IT.
THAT'S HOW YOU ROLL.
THAT'S HOW WE ROLL.
BETTER OPEN UP MAGIC.
GRAB THEM BY HAND.
SWEET, YOU CAN
REALLY SMELL IT.
YOU CAN CATCH
THAT PICKLING SPICE
RIGHT THERE.
SMELLS GOOD, HUH?
ADD A LITTLE MORE
PICKLING SPICE.
PUT THE BROWN SUGAR IN.
FILL IT WITH WATER.
WHAT GAS STATION DID YOU
RIP THAT OFF FROM?
LET HER SIMMER.
HOW DO THEY LOOK?
'TIL IT ALL
FALLS APART.
WHOA, SERVE ME UP.
(Guy)
ON A HUNK OF STEAMED CABBAGE.
LITTLE MUSTARD
ON THE SIDE.
THAT'S GREAT,
JUST FALLS APART.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD
CORNED BEEF.
IT'S SUPER TENDER.
THE FAT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH
LIKE BUTTER.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANT?
THAT ENDS IT ALL,
THAT GUY IS NUMBER ONE.
IT'S TENDER, FRESH.
VERY TASTY.
IT'S MY FAVORITE HERE.
EATING HERE IS LIKE
COMING HOME.
IT'S LIKE A SUNDAY MEAL.
IT'S THANKSGIVING ON A PLATE.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
GREAT.
CONSISTENTLY GOOD QUALITY.
I GUESS,
IN TODAY'S WORLD
THERE'S NOT MANY THINGS
THAT WE CAN COUNT ON
THAT ARE STAYING TRUE
TO WHAT IT WAS.
WE JUST LOVE IT HERE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
OH, SHE'S THROWING ME
SOME KNUCKLES.
GOTCHA.
I LIKE HER.
(Guy)
UP NEXT, CHICAGO.
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
(Guy)
TO A FAMILY JOINT DOING
HOMEMADE ITALIAN...
RAVIOLI, MEATBALLS.
(Guy)
FOR DECADES.
I COULD EAT THAT WHOLE BIRD.
YOU'RE DOING
A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
I KNOW.
SO GET THIS, RIGHT AFTER
HERBERT HOOVER
IS ELECTED PRESIDENT,
AND ITALIAN IMMIGRANT
BY THE NAME OF JOE DIBUONO
TAKES OVER TUFANO'S BAR HERE
IN CHICAGO'S LITTLE ITALY.
WELL, HE AND HIS WIFE START
COOKING UP CLASSIC
ITALIAN DISHES
OUT OF THEIR HOUSE
NEXT DOOR.
THREE GENERATIONS LATER,
THE FAMILY'S STILL RUNNING IT,
AND THE PLACE IS SO WELL KNOWN,
WELL, HEY, THEY DON'T EVEN
NEED A SIGN.
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
WE LOVE JOEY.
(Guy)
THAT'S JOEY DIBUONO, III
CARRYING ON THE FAMILY
TRADITION.
WALKING IN HERE IS LIKE
WALKING INTO HOME.
EVERYBODY KNOWS ABOUT IT.
IT'S THE PLACE TO BE
IF YOU WANT FAMILY STYLE,
AUTHENTIC ITALIAN FOOD.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
THIS PLACE IS,
IT'S A FAMILY RESTAURANT.
(Guy)
ALWAYS HAS BEEN,
AND NOW JOEY,
IS RUNNING IT
WITH HIS FAMILY.
ALFREDO SAUCE?
YOUR TWIN DAUGHTERS, ARE THEY
GONNA TAKE OVER?
YEAH, THEY'RE VERY
PERSONABLE.
THEY'RE VERY GOOD,
THEY'RE VERY AWARE.
THOSE TWO RUNNING THIS HOUSE,
OH, MY GOODNESS.
THAT'S SPECIAL FOR YOU,
RIGHT?
(Guy)
AND THEY'LL STILL BE SERVING UP
THE RED SAUCE CLASSICS...
THE MEATBALLS, THE SOFT SHELLS.
CAN I GET A GALLON
OF THAT TO GO?
(Guy)
AND ALL THE OTHER
FAMILY FAVORITES.
YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T HAVE
TO MAKE IT COMPLICATED.
SIMPLE FLAVORS, BUT NICE,
BIG TASTES.
THE FLAVOR'S IN THE FOOD.
THE MUSSELS ARE VERY GOOD.
PORK CHOPS.
THE LEMON CHICKEN
IS THE BEST THING THEY SERVE.
I HEARD THE LEMON CHICKEN
IS SUPPOSED TO BE
YOUR SPECIALTY,
AND THE BOMB.
EVERYBODY REALLY LOVES IT.
GET A WHOLE CHICKEN
AND JUST CUT IT UP.
PUT A LITTLE COOKING OIL,
A TOUCH OF OLIVE OIL.
THEN I GET SOME FRESH
GARLIC AND PEPPER.
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE OREGANO.
THEN YOU GET A FRESH
WHOLE LEMON,
AND YOU JUST
SQUEEZE IT RIGHT IN THERE.
LOOK AT THAT THING,
IT'S LIKE A VICE-GRIP.
HE'LL BE TAKING ROCKS
AND MAKING ROCK JUICE
IN A SECOND.
AND THEN THIS GOES
IN THE BROILER.
HOW LONG ARE WE
GOING TO GO DOWN.
WITH THIS HEAT IT COOKS
IN 15 MINUTES.
I'M EXPECTING MAGIC.
YOU'LL GET IT.
AND THEN WE USE POTATOES.
AND THIS IS WHAT
COMES ALONG SIDE OF IT?
IS THE BIG BIRD READY?
IT'S READY.
LOOK AT THE WAY THAT'S
ROASTED DOWN LIKE THAT.
IT REALLY HOLDS IN
THE JUICES.
GET A FEW OF THE POTATOES
AND ADD IT TO THE CHICKEN.
SPRINKLE IT WITH THE OIL
AND IT GIVES IT A GREAT TASTE.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WANT TO ARM WRESTLE
FOR THE THIGH?
I DON'T WANT TO
EMBARRASS YOU ON THE CAMERA.
LOOK AT THAT,
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S SUPER CRISPY.
NOW I GET A LITTLE
OF THE LEMON.
DEFINITELY PICKING UP
SOME OF THE OREGANO.
BREAST MEAT RIGHT THERE,
NICE AND SUPER JUICY.
I'M STARTING TO UNDERSTAND,
JOEY,
WHY YOU'RE SO POPULAR.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU, THAT'S
SOME BODACIOUS BIRD, BROTHER.
THAT'S TRIPLE B ON "TRIPLE D."
I COULD EAT
THAT WHOLE BIRD.
YOU'RE DOING
A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
I KNOW.
WELL DONE ON THE OUTSIDE
AND VERY TENDER ON THE INSIDE.
IT'S SPICY.
IT'S JUICY.
IT'S ONE OF
MY FAVORITES HERE.
IT'S A WONDERFUL
DISH.
IT'S SOMETHING I'VE BEEN
HAVING HERE FOR 25 YEARS.
YOU CAN'T FORGET
WHERE YOU'VE COME FROM
AND WHAT'S WORKED FOR YOU
ALL THESE YEARS.
DID YOU HAVE ENOUGH?
YOU BET.
(Guy)
ITALIAN FAMILY COOKING
THAT'S BECOME A LOCAL LEGEND.
THANK YOU.
DID YOU GROW UP HERE?
I WAS BROUGHT HERE
AS A KID.
MY MA'S BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 60 YEARS.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
COMING HERE?
17 YEARS.
12 OR 13 YEARS.
WE ALWAYS COME BACK HERE.
THEY ALWAYS REMEMBER YOU
WHEN YOU COME IN.
THEY TALK TO YOU.
ALL RIGHT HERE SO FAR?
HOW DOES IT FEEL TO BE
A LEGACY IN ITALIAN FOOD
IN CHICAGO?
I'M HONORED.
I'M HONORED THAT MY GRANDMA
AND GRANDPA WERE ABLE
TO START THIS.
IT'S A GREAT TRADITION.
A LOT OF PEOPLE COME HERE
FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
LET'S TALK ABOUT
WHO THEY ARE,
DICK VITALE, PHIL JACKSON,
BOB COSTAS.
WHO'S THIS CAT?
ROCKY MARCIANO.
THIS WAS MY GRANDPA HERE.
(Guy)
AND MAKING EVERYONE
FEEL AT HOME IS
A FAMILY TRADITION
JOEY'S PROUD TO CARRY ON.
WITH FOOD STRAIGHT
FROM HIS GRANDPARENT'S KITCHEN.
SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALL...
(Guy)
RIGHT DOWN TO THE TOMATO SAUCE
GRANDMA CALLED "RED GRAVY."
THIS IS THE WAY WE
WERE BROUGHT UP.
THIS IS THE WAY
MY GRANDPA AND GRANDMA
TAUGHT US.
SAUSAGE I SEE.
BEEF, COUPLE PIECES
OF PORK, TOO.
I'VE GOT NECK BONES.
NECK BONES.
THAT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
ANY RIB RIGHT THERE.
SO YOU GET A BUNCH
OF MARROW OUT OF THERE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET A TON
OF FLAVOR OUT OF THERE.
EVERYONE IN THE POOL.
TOMATOES.
ADD A LITTLE BASIL
TO IT.
AND THEN YOU JUST
LET IT GO DOWN
FOR ABOUT 3 1/2 HOURS.
HOW ABOUT YOU DO
THE REST OF THE SHOW BY YOURSELF
AND I'LL WATCH THIS.
LOOK AT THAT,
JUST GET IT GOING RIGHT HERE.
I HAVE A THING ABOUT GRAVY,
TOMATO SAUCE,
AND THAT IS, JUST
MAKE IT RIGHT,
JUST MAKE IT RIGHTEOUS.
MY FRIEND, THIS IS
RIGHT AND RIGHTEOUS.
FOR THAT YOU GET A HUG.
THE SAUCE IS OUT
OF THIS WORLD.
(Guy)
WHATEVER IT'S ON,
MOSTACCIOLI,
THE EGGPLANT PARMESAN,
AND THIS HEAVY HITTER...
CHICKEN PARM.
WINNER.
I'VE TRIED THE CHICKEN,
I'VE TRIED THE RAVIOLI.
THE MEATBALLS, PRETTY MUCH
EVERYTHING IS REAL GOOD.
FRIED CALAMARI.
SHELLS AND BROCCOLI.
VEAL PICCANTE.
(Guy)
JOEY SAYS THIS ONE'S
A NEWCOMER, HIS OWN RECIPE.
ON THE MENU ONLY TEN YEARS.
BRING IT ON.
INSIDE ROUND.
YOU DO THE VEAL TOP ROUND
ON EVERYTHING HERE.
YEAH, WE TRIM IT
AND CUT IT OURSELVES.
THAT'S OLD-SCHOOL.
TENDERIZE IT
A LITTLE BIT.
PUT THEM
IN THE FLOUR.
STRAIGHT EGG WASH.
AND THE BREAD CRUMBS
I USE THE WHITE BREAD CRUMBS
I DON'T USE THE REGULAR
HARD BREAD CRUMBS,
THAT'S WHAT MAKES ITS IT
SO GOOD.
START WITH
A LITTLE BUTTER.
AND THE VEAL DOESN'T
TAKE TO LONG TO COOK.
NO, IT DOESN'T.
I USE A LITTLE
LEMON JUICE.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S A NICE PORTION.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE
JUICE ON THERE.
SOME PINE NUTS.
THAT'S A NICE LOOKING
ROUND.
THERE'S TONS OF FLAVOR
IN THAT.
I COULD DO DAMAGE
ON THIS.
SUPER TENDER,
IT'S NICE AND LIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
THAT'S THE REAL-DEAL HOLY VEAL.
I'LL BE HERE ALL WEEK.
YOU SHOULD TRY THE VEAL.
AND DON'T FORGET
TO TIP YOUR WAITRESS.
HOW MANY YEARS I'VE WANTED
TO USE THAT LINE
AND IT FINALLY WORKED.
I'M OUT.
THE VEAL IS THE BEST
IN THE CITY.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD
AND FRESH.
IT COULDN'T BE DONE
ANY BETTER.
IT'S JUST A FAMILY PLACE.
I CAN TELL A LOT OF LOVE
WAS PUT INTO THIS.
YOU GOTTA LOVE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
AND THAT'S WHAT
WE DO HERE.
IT TASTES LIKE
HOMEMADE COOKING.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE
YOU CAN ADD.
THIS IS THE BEST ITALIAN
RESTAURANT IN THE CITY
OF CHICAGO.
JOEY, I CAN SEE WHY
EVERYBODY,
FROM THE AUNTS, TO YOUR MOM,
TO YOUR WIFE,
YOUR DAUGHTERS,
WHY EVERYBODY LOVES JOEY.
THANKS FOR SHARING IT
WITH US.
TWO SCRAMBLED, HAM.
(Guy)
UP NEXT, ATLANTA.
FOR GRITS AND GRAVY...
JUST LIKE GRANDMA'S.
AND ICEBOX PIE.
YOU'LL LIKE THIS.
SO THERE'S A TIME
IN YOUR LIFE
WHEN A FAMILY TRADITION
BECOMES KINDA LIKE
THE CORNERSTONE OF YOUR
FOOD FOUNDATION.
FOR ME, AT A YOUNG AGE
IT WAS SIMPLE,
GRITS, HAM,
AND RED-EYE GRAVY.
NOW, ON "TRIPLE D,"
YOU KNOW WE'VE GOT TO STOP
AT A PLACE KNOWN FOR THEIR
GREAT SOUTHERN BREAKFAST.
HERE WE ARE,
THE SILVER SKILLET IN ATLANTA.
GIVE ME A CHICKEN BISCUIT
AND TWO SCRAMBLED, HAM.
FRIED PORK CHOPS, GRITS.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
ENJOY.
COUNTY HAM IS SUCH
A SOUTHERN THING, I LOVE IT.
TRADITIONAL SOUTHERN FOOD.
(Guy)
THE SAME AS IN '67 WHEN
GEORGE DECKER BOUGHT THE JOINT.
MY FATHER HAD THE RESTAURANT
FOR 20 YEARS.
(Guy)
HIS DAUGHTER, TERESA TOOK OVER
IN THE LATE '80s.
THEN HER HUSBAND JEFF
STARTED PITCHING IN, TOO.
YOU'RE EATING MY FAVORITE
BREAKFAST.
GRITS AND HAM.
AND THESE ARE GREAT,
THEY'RE PERFECT.
DO YOU LIKE GRITS?
LOVE GRITS.
THIS IS THE RATIO?
YES.
SERIOUS.
WHY NOT BUTTER?
MARGARINE GIVES THEM
A BETTER FLAVOR.
MELTS AND SEEMS TO
HOLD UP BETTER OVER
THE LONG TERM.
I LIKE IT, AND THIS WAS
THE WAY YOUR DAD WAS DOING IT?
YEP.
BOILING WATER?
YES.
NOW, IT'S NOT SUPPOSED TO BE
A RAPID, SCREAMING BOIL.
THIS IS FINE, AS LONG AS
YOU CAN SEE THE...
DON'T WATCH IT,
IT WON'T BOIL.
NEXT, ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES,"
IT'S BOBBIN' FOR MARGARINE
IN A HOT POT OF BOILING WATER.
A LITTLE SALT.
AND THE MEASUREMENT STYLE
IS CALLED...
SOME.
NOW WE ADD THE GRITS.
NOW GO TO A SIMMER
AND COVER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS THE LID
FOR THIS POT.
CIRCA?
1956.
I HAVE TO GET
THIS COOKWARE SET.
YOU CAN ONLY BUY IT
FROM HERE.
OKAY, SO HOW ARE
OUR GRITS?
WE'RE DONE.
LOOK AT THAT,
NICE AND CREAMY.
NOW SHOULD WE TASTE THEM,
ABSOLUTELY.
I JUST WANT TO TASTE THEM
IN THEIR NATURAL STATE.
OKAY.
I LIKE IT WITH
THE MARGARINE LIKE THAT.
THEY'RE TASTY,
I LOVE GRITS.
I'D EAT THEM IN A BOAT
WITH A GOAT,
IN A HOUSE WITH A MOUSE.
JUST TASTE LIKE GRITS
ARE SUPPOSED TO TASTE.
IT'S THE CLOSEST THING
TO HOME COOKING.
IT MAKES YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE IN YOUR OWN KITCHEN.
EXCEPT YOU DON'T HAVE TO COOK
OR CLEAN UP.
THE WAITRESSES ARE VERY NICE
AND VERY FRIENDLY.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE, DEAR?
THEY'RE "DARLIN', SWEETIE,
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?"
SOUTHERN HOSPITALITY,
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ABOUT.
BECAUSE IT'S AN
OLD-TIMEY PLACE.
IT'S AN OLD-TIMEY JOINT.
IT'S HARD TO REPRODUCE THAT
IF IT'S NOT THE REAL DEAL.
THOSE SIGNS HAVE BEEN THERE
FOR 50 YEARS?
THEY'RE THE ORIGINAL
HAND-PAINTED SIGNS.
EVERYTHING IS JUST LIKE
IT WAS WHEN THEY BUILT IT.
(Guy)
ESPECIALLY THE FAVORITES.
GOT PORK CHOP ON THE EGG.
EGGS, GRITS,
BISCUITS.
THE BISCUITS ARE GREAT.
THEY'RE REALLY MOIST
AND FLUFFY.
GOOD BISCUIT,
NICE AND LIGHT.
A SCRAMBLED EGG
AND CHEESE BISCUIT.
CHICKEN BISCUIT.
BACON JELLY BISCUIT.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
THE JELLY ON IT.
EIGHT COUNTRY HAM
BISCUITS.
IT'S THAT SOUTHERN HAM,
IT'S FABULOUS.
IT'S A REAL SALTY HAM.
TAKE THE SLICE OF HAM.
AND JUST LET ME
EAT IT NOW.
OPEN WIDE.
TRIM THE HAM.
IS THIS REALLY THE KNIFE
YOU USE?
IT IS.
I KNOW WHAT TO GET YOU
FOR CHRISTMAS.
EACH PIECE WE
DO THIS TO?
EVERY PIECE.
HAND TRIMMED.
SO IT'S HAND-TO-HAM COMBAT.
OKAY, I'LL GIVE
YOU THAT ONE.
THEY HAVE TO HAVE
THE BONE IN THEM?
BONE-IN FOR COUNTRY HAM.
IS THIS THE WAY EVERYBODY
MAKES THIS DOWN HERE IN ATLANTA?
NO, THIS IS A SKILLET
SECRET FAMILY RECIPE,
HANDED DOWN FROM
MY DAD.
SOY SAUCE?
SOY SAUCE.
BY THE GALLON,
WOW.
AND THAT'S BROWN SUGAR.
LIGHT BROWN SUGAR.
PAPRIKA.
WHAT IS THIS, COFFEE?
THIS IS NOT COFFEE,
THIS IS A SECRET SAUCE.
THAT'S COLA.
SOY SAUCE, BROWN SUGAR,
PAPRIKA,
COLA,
SOUNDS LIKE BREAKFAST
DOESN'T IT?
THE HAM IS NOW GOING
TO GO IN THE MAGIC MIXTURE.
PIECE BY PIECE.
'CAUSE IF YOU STICK THEM
IN THERE AS A CLUMP,
IT WON'T GET TO THE MIDDLE.
MARINATES OVER NIGHT.
YOUR HAM IS DONE,
YOU COOK THAT.
YOU GONNA DRAG THAT
OVER MY TENNIES?
NOW HOW DO WE MAKE
THE RED-EYE GRAVY?
WE TAKE THE JUICE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
JUST STAND THERE
AND LOOK PRETTY.
WANT ME TO MOVE THIS AROUND
AND MAKE IT MORE DIFFICULT?
DON'T YOU DARE.
ADD OUR HOT COFFEE.
AND THAT IS THE
RED-EYE GRAVY.
THAT'S THE RED-EYE GRAVY.
RED-EYE GRAVY,
A BOWL OF GRITS,
GOOD TO GO.
LET ME SHOW YOU HOW
WE DO IT AT MY HOUSE.
THROW THOSE GRITS DOWN THERE.
I CUT ALL MY HAM UP
AHEAD OF TIME,
LIKE MY GRANDFATHER
USED TO DO IT.
I'M REALLY HAPPY
THAT YOU USED THE SIDE
WITH THE BONE.
THAT'S THE BEST.
LET ME JUST TRY
THE GRAVY NOW.
NOW THE RED-EYE GRAVY
TASTE MORE LIKE MY
RED-EYE GRAVY.
YOU CAN TELL I DON'T
LIKE THIS AT ALL.
I'M GONNA PUT THIS
IN MY CAR.
IT'S EXCELLENT,
EXTREMELY SALTY.
I THINK IT TASTES
DELICIOUS.
THE RED-EYE GRAVY
IS REAL UNIQUE.
JUST LIKE GRANDMA'S.
(Guy)
AND HEY, GRANDMA MADE
DESSERT, TOO.
LEMON ICEBOX PIE,
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WITH A PIECE THAT BIG,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO PUSH
THE CAMARO TO MY NEXT DINER.
(Guy)
THE SILVER SKILLET HAS BEEN AN
ATLANTA INSTITUTION SINCE 1956.
IT'S A LANDMARK HERE
IN ATLANTA.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S A '50s DINNER,
STICK-TO-YOUR RIBS FOOD.
(GUY)
TERESA BRECKINRIDGE HAS
KEPT IT ALL GOING
SINCE SHE TOOK IT OVER
FROM HER DAD.
IT'S A GOOD
SOUTHERN BREAKFAST.
(Guy)
WITH ALL KINDS
OF SOUTHERN CLASSICS,
AND THAT INCLUDES DESSERT.
LEMON ICEBOX PIE.
THE PIE IS EXCEPTIONAL.
ICEBOX MEANS
IT'S KEPT COLD.
RIGHT.
BUT IT GETS BAKED?
YES.
CRUST FIRST?
WE'RE GONNA DO THE CRUST FIRST.
A COUPLE OF HANDFULS OF
GRAHAM CRACKER CRUMBS.
LIQUID MARGARINE.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS
TOGETHER.
PUT IT IN THE OVEN
FOR 20 MINUTES.
NOW TO MAKE
THE CUSTARD.
EGGS, WE ONLY USE
THE YOLK.
WOW, LOOK AT
THAT BOWL.
A.D.
IT CAME WITH
THE OTHER SET.
SWEETENED
CONDENSED MILK.
YOUR DAD'S RECIPE
ALSO?
YES.
THIS MAN HAD IT
GOING ON.
HE DID.
LEMONS.
EN GARDE.
SORRY, HOW MANY?
EIGHT.
SQUEEZE THEM BY HAND.
I'M GONNA HAMMER
YOU DOWN LIKE THAT.
SOMETIMES I DON'T EVEN
KNOW MY OWN STRENGTH.
YOU'VE BEEN PLAYING AROUND
AND I'VE BEEN WORKING.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO WIN.
THAT'S A LOT OF MIXTURE
FOR ONE PIE.
IT IS, BUT IT WILL
TIGHTEN UP.
WILL IT FIT?
IT'LL FIT.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE
DONE THIS BEFORE.
A FEW TIMES.
AND NOW WE'RE GOING
TO HIT IT WITH WHAT?
A FEW VANILLA WAFERS,
GENTLY PUSH THEM DOWN IN.
NOW WE BAKE IT?
20 MINUTES.
THEN YOU LET IT
COOL DOWN.
THEN WE HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE...
CREAM TOPPING.
THAT'S A LOT OF PIE,
HEAVY.
OOH, I LIKE THAT,
A LITTLE CRUNCH ON TOP.
WHAT WOULD BE NICE THERE
IS A LITTLE LEMON ZEST.
BUT YOU KNOW,
ON A DIFFERENT DAY.
WITH A PIECE THAT BIG,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO PUSH
THE CAMARO TO MY
NEXT DINER.
I LIKE GRAHAM CRACKER
ON THE BOTTOM.
THAT HAS GOT TO BE
SO REFRESHING
ON A HOT DAY.
IT'S NOT OVERLY SWEET.
NO.
GOOD LITTLE AMOUNT
OF CITRUS.
JUST ENOUGH TART
TO KINDA...
IT LETS YOU KNOW
IT'S THERE.
YOU WOULD LIKE THIS.
THE PIE WAS DELICIOUS.
THERE'S A LOT OF LOVE
WENT IN TO THAT PIE.
YOU'RE RUNNING LATE,
KIDDO.
SOUTHERN CHARM
AND HOSPITALITY.
THE ATLANTA, AUTHENTIC
EXPERIENCE.
FANTASTIC.
EXCELLENT.
THIS IS GOOD FOOD.
(Guy)
THE WAY THEY'VE BEEN
DOING IT HERE FOR
HALF A CENTURY.
UNFORTUNATELY,
I CAN'T DOUBLE DIP.
I SHOULD HAVE GONE WITH MORE
OF A BIG BITE STYLE.
THE BIG BOY SPOON.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
BUT WE'VE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON "TRIPLE D."
♪