HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THE WAY YOUR MOM
OR YOUR GRANDMA WOULD MAKE IT.
FAMILY FAVORITES
IN CENTRAL CALIFORNIA...
HEY, YOU GUYS ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS THE PLACE WE COME
TO SEE EVERYBODY.
DOWN HOME ITALIAN...
LASAGNAS, RAVIOLIS.
WHERE ONE FAMILY'S BEEN SERVIN'
THEIR FAVORITES...
MOLTO BENE.
FOR NEARLY A CENTURY.
MMM, THAT WAS GREAT.
IN ARIZONA...
CHICKEN SCHNITZEL UP.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
MADE FROM SCRATCH.
SPAETZLE GOING OUT.
WHERE THIS COUPLE'S SERVIN'
WHAT THEIR GRANDPARENTS DID...
OH, YEAH!
BACK IN GERMANY.
MMM. THAT IS GREAT.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING
BETTER THAN THIS.
THEN IN DALLAS...
WHEN YOU COME IN HERE,
YOU'RE ONE OF THE FAMILY.
WHERE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS...
YOUR FOLKS KNOW
YOU'RE OUT?
ARE DOIN' THE PIZZA
THEY GREW UP WITH...
PICK UP PIE.
IN ILLINOIS.
THE CRUST IS SO THIN,
AND THE INGREDIENTS
JUST TASTE FRESH.
MY UNCLE SAM
USED TO CALL THIS
(deep voice) "GIMME ONE A THEM
GARBAGE PIZZAS,
EVERYTHING ON THE PIZZA."
SCARE ME IF I WAS A KID.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON TRIPLE-"D"
I TRAVEL ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
AND END UP
IN THE MOST UNIQUE AREAS.
HERE I AM
IN THE SACRAMENTO RIVER DELTA
ON A MECHANICAL BRIDGE.
NOW 25 MILES THAT WAY
IS SACRAMENTO.
25 MILES THAT WAY IS STOCKTON.
BUT THE OASIS IS THIS JOINT,
GIUSTI'S--
SINCE 1912, A HUNTER'S
AND FISHERMAN'S PARADISE.
OKEYDOKEY.
EVERYBODY WANTS
TO COME TO GIUSTI'S.
IT'S OUT OF THE WAY,
AND IT'S IN THE DELTA.
YOU FEEL RELAXED
AND ALWAYS GET A GOOD MEAL.
THE FOOD'S AWESOME.
THE WAY YOUR MOM
OR YOUR GRANDMA WOULD MAKE IT.
AND SERVE IT...
(man) IT LOOKS GOOD.
FAMILY STYLE.
YOU GONNA BE ABLE
TO FINISH ALL THAT?
PROBABLY NOT.
HAVE SOME MORE WINE.
IT FEELS LIKE YOU'RE
STEPPING BACK A FEW DECADES.
OR ALMOST A CENTURY...
YOU GUYS ALL RIGHT?
WHEN MARK MORAIS'S GRANDFATHER,
EGISTO GIUSTI,
TOOK OVER THIS SALOON
BACK IN 1912.
MY GRANDFATHER WOULD GET
A BAR FULL OF PEOPLE.
MY GRANDMOTHER, SHE'D COOK 'EM
UP SOMETHING TO EAT.
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
THESE DAYS,
MARK'S RUNNIN' THE JOINT.
GINNY, YOU GUYS
ALL RIGHT?
YEP.
IT'S HOMEMADE.
FROM THE FRIED CHICKEN
TO THE LAMB SHANKS...
EXCELLENT.
TO GRANDMA'S
MINESTRONE SOUP.
ALWAYS AWESOME.
SERVED HERE EVER SINCE
THE BEGINNING?
AS LONG AS I CAN
REMEMBER.
IT IS A TRUE
MINESTRONE SOUP.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
WHAT GOES IN FIRST?
WE GET A POTFUL
OF BOILIN' WATER.
AND THEN WE DUMP IN PINTO BEANS,
WHITE BEANS, PEARL BARLEY.
AND THEN WE'LL THROW IN
THE CARROTS, CELERY, ZUCCHINI.
THROW IN THE CABBAGE, ONION.
AND THEN WE'LL THROW IN
THE SPINACH.
SO EVERYBODY.
A LITTLE GARLIC,
PUT A LITTLE CHICKEN BASE,
A LITTLE BEEF.
BASIL.
AND THEN SOME
OF THE MEAT SCRAPS.
CHICK OR BEEF?
USUALLY JUST THE BEEF.
NO SALT.
THE BEEF AND THE CHICKEN BASE
KINDA GIVE IT ENOUGH SALT.
COVER IT.
I LIKE IT.
WE LET IT BOIL.
THEN WE TURN IT DOWN
AND SIMMER IT ALL NIGHT,
COME BACK IN THE MORNING,
AND WE DUMP IN THE ORZO.
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE RICE.
TURN IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT,
BECAUSE IF YOU DON'T,
THEY'LL END UP STICKIN'.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHAT, DID YOU
GUYS FIND THAT ON THE DELTA?
THIS WAS AN OLD OAR THAT I USED
FOR MY BOAT YEARS AGO.
WHY DO I THINK
THAT'S TRUE?
WHO GETS TO BE
THE OFFICIAL TASTER?
WE REALLY DON'T HAVE
AN OFFICIAL TASTER...
(clears throat)
BECAUSE THE RECIPE
IS THE SAME EVERY TIME.
OH.
UNLESS YOU WANT TO BE
THE OFFICIAL TASTER.
WELL, I CAN--I CAN JUMP
RIGHT IN THAT IF YOU MAKE ME,
IF YOU TWIST MY ARM,
YOU KNOW, AND--AND...
A NICE HEARTY BOWL
OF MINESTRONE.
HOLY MOLY MINESTRONE.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S CREAMY.
THE BEANS ARE STILL TENDER.
THE BARLEY MAKES IT. MMM.
SERIOUSLY,
YOU GOTTA TRY IT.
MOLTO BENE.
AND THEN SOME. I'LL GO AHEAD
AND KEEP EATIN',
IF YOU WANNA JUST...
THAT'S ALL RIGHT. YOU KEEP
EATING. I GOT A LOT MORE SOUP.
THAT WAS GOOD.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKED IT.
YEAH, I COULD PROBABLY GET
A LITTLE BIT MORE, THOUGH.
GLAD YOU--
HAVE A LITTLE MORE.
OKAY. NOW I'M DONE.
THAT WAS GREAT.
FINITO.
IT'S JUST ONE OF THE BEST SOUPS
I'VE HAD.
OH, THE SOUP'S
FANTASTIC.
'CAUSE, HEY, THE RECIPE'S
ONLY ABOUT A HUNDRED YEARS OLD.
YOU HAVEN'T CHANGED MUCH.
NO, ORIGINAL BAR.
A BEER COOLER
AND EVERYTHING.
THE BEER COOLER
WAS BUILT
BY MY GRANDFATHER'S COUSIN.
STILL STAYS COLD.
THAT'S THE ORIGINAL CASH
REGISTER--WORKS LIKE A CHARM.
WOW.
THE BAR IS REALLY INTERESTING
WITH ALL THE HATS.
THE PLACE IS FUNKY.
FARMERS, PROFESSIONALS,
ATTORNEYS. YOU GOT BOATERS.
ALL RIGHT?
JUST STUMBLED UPON IT
OUT ON A BOAT RIDE,
LOVED IT.
(man) THEY ALL JUST KINDA
COME IN AND MIX.
I WAS BORN AND RAISED IN THIS
TOWN. THESE ARE ALL MY FRIENDS.
THIS IS THE PLACE WE COME
TO SEE EVERYBODY.
FRESH GARLIC.
THEY'VE BEEN DOIN' IT
FOR SO LONG,
THEY JUST KNOW
WHAT'S GOOD.
LASAGNAS, RAVIOLIS.
AND THEIR PESTO--
MY ABSOLUTE FAVORITE.
AND A RECENT ADDITION...
LAMB SHANK.
THEY'VE ONLY BEEN DOIN'
THIS SPECIAL FOR 25 YEARS.
DOWN-HOME ITALIAN,
A LOT OF TOMATO SAUCE,
REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA DO LAMB SHANKS
WITH POLENTA.
POLENTA'S AN OLD ITALIAN STAPLE,
'CAUSE IT'S MORE TRADITIONAL.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
WITH THE SHANKS?
ADD A LITTLE WATER
TO 'EM.
A LITTLE BRINE
THROUGH OSMOSIS...
YEP, A LITTLE OSMOSIS.
INCORPORATE
SOME OF THAT SEASONING.
A LITTLE SUGAR,
A LITTLE SALT.
GONNA JUST KIND OF STIR IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
LET 'EM SET OVERNIGHT.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE 'EM
OUT OF THE BRINE.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT 'EM
IN THE FLOUR.
A LITTLE SEASONED
FLOUR THERE.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF SEASONING IN IT,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE PEPPER, A LITTLE SALT.
AND WHILE WE'RE WAITIN',
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE BUTTER.
SO OLIVE OIL TO COOK IT IN,
BUTTER FOR SOME FLAVOR.
DREDGE THESE,
PUT 'EM IN THE PAN.
NOW HOW MANY COME
ON AN ORDER?
HOW MANY DO YOU WANT?
I LIKE THE ATTITUDE.
PUT A LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA BROWN 'EM
PRETTY GOOD.
I'M GONNA TRANSFER 'EM
TO MY BAKING PAN.
AND I'M GONNA SAUTé
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION,
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSHROOM...
A LITTLE FENNEL--
I LIKE THAT.
CARROT, A LITTLE CELERY,
A LITTLE MORE GARLIC.
OH, YOU'VE WORKED ON THIS LINE
ENOUGH TIMES.
THEN I ADD
A LITTLE ORANGE JUICE.
OKAY, A LITTLE ACID,
GOT IT.
THEN I ADD A LITTLE RED WINE
OVER HERE,
A LITTLE RED WINE HERE.
GONNA SAUTé THESE.
THEY'RE ABOUT DONE.
I'M GONNA PUT 'EM
RIGHT OVER THE SHANKS...
NICE.
AND EVEN IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
I'M GONNA PUT SOME
CRUSHED TOMATO SAUCE IN HERE.
(whistles)
A LOT OF LOVE GOIN' ON
FOR THAT--SIX LITTLE SHANKS.
COVER 'EM UP PRETTY GOOD.
A LITTLE OREGANO.
OREG--OREGANO.
AND THIS YOU'RE GROWING
OUT THERE IN THE GARDEN?
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE FRESH SPRIGS OF OREGANO,
PUT THE SAUCE ON TOP
AND EVERYTHING DOWN,
THAT WAY
IT'LL SETTLE DOWN.
AND HIT IT
WITH THE TIN FOIL.
COVER IT UP, AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT IN A 350-DEGREE OVEN.
THREE HOURS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHOA, LOOK HOW THAT
COOKS DOWN.
WELL, WE'LL GIVE YOU A LITTLE
GRAVY FROM THE LAMB SHANKS
INTO THE POLENTA,
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE SAUCE,
A LITTLE PARMESAN,
A LITTLE GARNISH.
(whistles)
BON APPéTIT.
MMM. WOW, THAT'S TENDER.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S GOT A NICE CRUST TO IT.
IT'S BEYOND
FALL-OFF-THE-BONE TENDER.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT.
YOU CAN MASH IT WITH A FORK.
THE SAUCE HAS GOT
OUTSTANDING FLAVOR. MMM.
AND THE POLENTA--CREAMY,
GOOD CHEW TO IT STILL.
THERE'S STILL TEXTURE TO IT.
I'D ORDER THAT EVERY TIME.
REALLY DELICIOUS.
GREAT.
BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
BUT EVERYTHING THEY PREPARE
IS GREAT.
DO CHICKEN OVER PESTO.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE
LIKE GIUSTI'S.
THERE YOU GO.
WHEN YOU'RE BOATIN' THROUGH
HERE, OR YOU'RE GOIN' FISHIN'
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
STOP AND EATIN' THIS... MAN.
TWO LAMB SHANKS, SANDY.
MARK KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOIN'.
A LITTLE FETTUCCINE.
DIDN'T GO TO CULINARY SCHOOL.
JUST SAT AROUND AND WATCHED.
DOESN'T MATTER.
YOUR GRANDMOTHER GAVE YOU
A PhD--PRETTY HEAVY DISH.
THAT WAS A GOOD ONE.
UP NEXT...
IT'S GOOD HOME COOKING.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO ARIZONA...
DELICIOUS.
FOR COMFORT FOOD.
CHICKEN SCHNITZEL.
GERMAN-STYLE.
IT TASTES LIKE
BACK IN GERMANY.
MMM. I'VE HAD SCHNITZEL...
BUT NOT LIKE THAT.
WHAT A GREAT DISH.
♪♪
HERE ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
WE KNOW NO BOUNDARIES
OF REGION, SIZE OR CUISINE.
MATTER OF FACT, WE'VE DONE
ITALIAN, MEXICAN,
AMERICAN, BARBECUE--HECK,
YOU NAME IT, WE'VE DONE IT ALL.
WE'VE EVEN DONE
CHINESE-JAMAICAN FUSION.
BUT ONE WE HAVEN'T DONE
IS GERMAN.
AND THAT BRINGS US HERE
TO GLENDALE, ARIZONA,
TO HAUS MURPHY'S.
CHICKEN SCHNITZEL UP.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
THIS FOOD IS
VERY HOMEMADE.
(woman) SAUERBRATEN
FOR YOU WITH SPAETZLE.
IT TASTES LIKE
BACK IN GERMANY.
BROTHER, WHAT ARE YOU HAVIN',
BEER AND PRETZEL?
AN ENORMOUS PRETZEL, YEAH.
PAPRIKA SCHNITZEL.
CRUNCHY AND TASTY.
SEHR GUT. I MEAN,
VERY GOOD IN GERMAN.
IT'S GOOD HOME COOKING.
HEARTY FOOD MADE
FROM SCRATCH.
THERE YOU ARE.
THE KIND ROSE HOFFMANN
GREW UP ON IN MUNICH...
THANK YOU.
AND HER HUSBAND BRETT LEARNED
FROM HIS GERMAN GRANDPARENTS
HERE IN ARIZONA.
BRATS GOIN' DOWN.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU THAT YOU MAKE?
SAUERBRATEN.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S A DELICIOUS
SWEET-AND-SOUR POT ROAST.
"SAUER" IS SOUR...
SOUR.
AND "BRATEN" MEANS...
ROAST.
WE'RE MAKING A SOUR ROAST.
YEAH, BASICALLY.
MMM!
IT'S A BIG TOP ROUND.
THAT'S MY SCIMITAR.
DO YOU WEAR THIS IN A SHEATH
AND JOG THROUGH THE FOREST?
A LITTLE SCARY.
WE'RE GONNA TRIM IT.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT DOWN.
THEN A--
WE GET TO MAKE NOISE.
NOISE. MEAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR LIQUID--THE VINEGAR.
OKAY, A LITTLE BUTTERMILK.
A LITTLE BUTTERMILK.
SO THAT'S THE SOUR PART.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A MIREPOIX.
ONIONS, CARROTS, CELERY.
THEN WE GO FOR OUR SEASONINGS--
WHOLE PEPPERCORNS...
BAY LEAF.
CLOVE, NUTMEG,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT...
JUST A TOUCH.
AND WHITE PEPPER.
WHITE--
MIX THIS ALL UP.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA MARINATE?
THIS IS GONNA MARINATE, UH,
AT LEAST FOUR TO FIVE DAYS.
DAYS?
DAYS.
POP A LID ON.
OKAY, IN THE WALK-IN
FOR FOUR TO FIVE DAYS.
YEP.
AND NOW WE'RE READY
TO PROCEED TO OUR BROWNING.
WE'RE ADDING THE OIL
TO OUR POT--SWEET.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
OUR ONIONS IN.
LET THAT COOK
FOR A COUPLE MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR LOVELY, LOVELY MEAT.
GET MOST OF THE MOISTURE OUT.
IT SMELLS LIKE SOUR.
IT SHOULD SMELL REAL SOUR.
THIS IS BROKEN DOWN.
SMELL THAT.
SO THIS DOESN'T GO
IN THE OVEN?
EVERYTHING
IS STOVETOP.
SO WE'RE GONNA BROWN 'EM ON
ALL SIDES. DOES IT GET A COVER?
IT NEVER GETS A COVER. THIS IS
A 3-HOUR PROCESS TO DO THIS.
WANNA GRAB A CHAIR
AND A BEER...
I WAS JUST GONNA SAY
LET'S GO GET A BEER, YEAH.
AND WE CAN JUST SIT HERE
FOR A WHILE. YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
RED WINE AND DEGLAZE THAT
A LITTLE BIT. NOW IT'S
TIME TO STAB MY MEAT.
LET ALL THAT JUICE OUT.
IT JUST ADDS
TO THE GRAVY FLAVOR.
WE LET THAT COOK
FOR A FEW MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR MARINADE TO THAT.
SO THE MARINADE
THAT WE HAD...
YEP.
FIVE DAYS...
NOW JUST GOT POURED
BACK IN ON TOP OF THE MEAT.
BACK IN ON TOP
OF OUR MEAT.
MMM.
WELCOME TO ANOTHER EDITION,
"AS THE SAUER BRATENS."
WE'RE GONNA COOK THAT DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR MEAT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA STRAIN
THE OIL OFF.
THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN
THE MARINADE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
MAKE GRAVY.
AT LEAST THIS IS FAST.
NOW THE CORNSTARCH SLURRY.
YEP.
WOW, LOOK HOW FAST
THAT TIGHTENED UP.
NOW OUR KITCHEN BOUQUET...
DARK COLOR THERE.
SOME WHITE PEPPER,
A PINCH OF SALT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR BROWN SUGAR.
YOU HAVE TO KEEP TASTING THIS.
A LITTLE MORE BROWN SUGAR.
TOO SOUR?
TOO SOUR, YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR RAISINS--
BRINGS OUT ANOTHER TYPE
OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
AND SO THIS IS A DELICACY.
I MEAN, WHEN PEOPLE COME OUT
FOR GERMAN FOOD
AT HAUS MURPHY'S...
YEP.
THAT THEY'RE
REALLY EXCITED TO HAVE.
YEAH, THEY ARE.
AS HARD AS IT TAKES
TO MAKE IT...
EXACTLY.
NOBODY WANTS TO DO THIS
AT HOME. MM-HMM.
THAT IS GREAT.
IT'S NOT TOO TENDER.
MNH-MNH.
IT'S NOT TOO TOUGH,
BUT THERE IS A CONTRAST,
A SWEET...
AND SOUR.
MMM. BUT IT REALLY TAKES
THAT LONG?
IT REALLY TAKES
THAT LONG.
THERE'S NOT, LIKE...
THERE'S NO SHORTCUT.
YOU LIKE THE SWEET
AND THE SOUR?
I DO LIKE THE SWEET
AND THE SOUR. IT'S VERY GOOD.
DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING
BETTER THAN THIS.
REAL GERMAN FOOD.
SERVED THE REAL GERMAN WAY.
(Mark) IT'S SOCIAL FOOD.
I MEAN, IN GERMANY,
YOU SIT FOR HOURS
AND EAT AND TALK AND ENJOY.
HERE WE PROMOTE
"SIT, STAY, ENJOY."
OH, YEAH!
WHATEVER YOU'RE HAVING...
HERE COMES THE BRATWURST.
FROM BASIC BRATS...
IT'S VERY GOOD
WITH THE SAUERKRAUT
TO BEEF ROULADEN
STUFFED WITH BACON,
ONIONS AND PICKLES...
I REALLY DON'T NEED THE KNIFE.
IT JUST FALLS APART.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TO SCRATCH-MADE SPAETZLE...
AND THAT LOOKS
LIKE SO MUCH FUN.
IT'S A PASTA WITH A LITTLE
GRAVY SAUCE ON IT. MMM.
TO THEIR MOST POPULAR DISH,
SCHNITZEL...
WE HAVE A JAEGER
AND A WIENER SCHNITZEL.
THE SCHNITZEL IS FULL OF FLAVOR.
DONE SEVEN DIFFERENT WAYS.
CHICKEN SCHNITZEL
FOR YOU.
THE PAPRIKA SCHNITZEL.
VERY TASTY--IT HAS
A MILD, PEPPERY FLAVOR.
VERY GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
PAPRIKA GRAVY RIGHT NOW.
FOR SCHNITZEL.
YES.
SO WE'VE GOT BACON
DOWN INTO OIL.
OKAY,
NOW WE CAN ADD OUR ONIONS,
CHICKEN BASE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR PAPRIKA.
AND THIS IS HUNGARIAN PAPRIKA,
BY THE WAY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT.
IT'S GOT A NICER COLOR
AND A BETTER FLAVOR.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR WATER TO IT.
AND JUST LET THIS SIT HERE
AND SIMMER.
WHEN THAT'S DONE,
THEN WE'RE GONNA THICKEN IT UP
AND FINISH IT OFF.
AND YOU'RE MAKING A ROUX
WITH FLOUR AND OIL.
ACTUALLY, I USE BUTTER.
IT GIVES IT A BETTER FLAVOR.
SO YOU GO 50-50
TO THE FAT TO THE FLOUR.
YEP.
NOW IT TIGHTENS UP NICE.
YEAH. NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR WHITE PEPPER.
AND WHAT DO WE GOT THERE?
THAT'S YELLOW CURRY.
IN GERMAN FOOD?
YES. THEY USE A LOT
OF CURRY IN GERMAN FOOD.
CAN I GIVE THAT
A LITTLE TASTE?
YEP.
MMM. YEAH, THAT'S NICE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE OUR SCHNITZEL.
DIG IT. SO THIS IS FROM
THE HIND LEG OF THE PORK.
YEP.
NOW WE GO TO THE MACHINE.
(whistles)
WE PERFORATE IT,
AND THAT'S WHAT WE GET.
WE'RE GONNA BREAD THIS
IN FLOUR THAT'S SEASONED,
EGG WASH AND BREADCRUMBS.
AND SO YOU PAN-FRY IT
LIGHTLY LIKE THIS...
YES, WE DO.
NOT IN THE DEEP FRYER.
NOT IN--NO. THAT'S...
AH.
THAT'S SACRILEGE.
THAT'S A NO-NO.
BUT YOU DO THROW
A LITTLE HOT OIL UP ON TOP.
YEP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO TO THE PLATE.
THEN WE LADLE.
MMM. THAT'S NICE.
I'VE HAD SCHNITZEL.
BUT NOT LIKE THAT.
I'VE NEVER HAD IT LIKE THAT.
THAT'S GOT SOME KILLER CRUNCH.
WELL, THE SAUCE IS MONEY.
THAT PAPRIKA CHANGES IT ALL.
DELICIOUS. WHAT A GREAT DISH.
IT IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD,
FRIED TO PERFECTION.
THE SAUCE IS VERY MILD,
BUT IT'S GOT FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S NOT ANYTHING
THAT WE CAN GET AT HOME.
AND FOR YOU,
THE KASSELER.
THERE'S LARGE PORTIONS,
AND THEY'RE VERY TASTY.
YOU'RE ALLOWED TO UNDO YOUR BELT
HERE AT HAUS MURPHY'S.
REALLY? PRICES ARE
KIND OF CHEAP.
YEAH.
CHEAP PRICES
AND LOTS OF BEER.
LOTS OF BEER.
I NEED THE KNOCKWURST, DEAR.
RIGHT HERE.
IT'S A UNIQUE PLACE IF YOU WANT
TO TRY THAT GERMAN ENVIRONMENT
AND FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
NOT IN ARIZONA.
IT'S JUST SO NICE
AND FRIENDLY,
LIKE BEING A PART
OF A FAMILY.
WE HAVE A GREAT TIME
EVERY TIME WE COME.
(Guy) WHERE'S
YOUR MOM FROM?
SHE'S ACTUALLY
FROM BERLIN, GERMANY,
SO I KNOW GOOD GERMAN FOOD.
THIS FOOD IS WAY BETTER THAN
MY MOM'S. IT'S A SECRET, THOUGH.
SHH.
DON'T TELL. DON'T TELL.
NEXT STOP, TEXAS...
THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
WOW.
WHERE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS
ARE DOIN' BAR FOOD THEIR WAY.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
THIS LITTLE TRICK?
SOME GUY.
THE BACK EAST IS COMIN'
OUT OF THE DALLAS BOY
RIGHT NOW--"SOME GUY."
♪♪
NOW WHEN I SAY FAMILY FAVORITE,
YOU COULD BE THINKIN',
WELL, FAMILY DOG,
FAMILY VACATION,
BUT FOR A LOT OF FOLKS LIKE ME,
FAMILY FAVORITE IS FOOD.
NOW I'M HERE IN EAST DALLAS,
WHERE FOR OVER 20 YEARS,
TWO BROTHERS
FROM OUTSIDE OF CHICAGO
HAVE BEEN SERVIN' UP SOME
MIDWESTERN FAMILY RECIPES
AT A PLACE CALLED LOUIE'S.
IT'S A BAR-BAR.
IT'S A REAL BAR.
YOU EXPECT TO GET
MARTINIS HERE.
WHAT'S SHAKIN'.
I WOULD EXPECT TO GET
APPLIANCE REPLACEMENT PARTS.
OR MAYBE...
PICKUP, PLEASE.
HAND-CUT STEAK.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE FOOD.
GRILLED PORK CHOP
WITH BROCCOLI.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
YOU'VE GOT PASTAS.
YOU GOT CALZONE,
THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
THEY PUT EVERYTHING
THAT THEY HAVE INTO IT.
(man) ORDER OF CRAB CLAWS.
THEY ARE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS
FROM WAUKEGAN, ILLINOIS.
CHRIS RUNS THE KITCHEN...
TWO PIES OUT,
GREEK SALAD GONE.
AND LOUIE RUNS THE FRONT.
YOUR FOLKS KNOW
YOU'RE OUT?
WHAT'S YOUR LAST NAME?
CANELAKES.
THESE GUYS GOT THIS PLACE
ROLLIN' MORE THAN 20 YEARS AGO.
PIZZA. THAT'S IT.
'CAUSE LOUIE MOVED TO TOWN
AND SAID, "HEY"...
PICK UP PIE.
"WHERE'S THE DECENT PIZZA?"
I CALLED MY BROTHER.
I GO, "WE'RE GOING INTO
THE PIZZA BUSINESS IN DALLAS."
GET OUT HERE.
SO CHRIS MOVED OUT.
BLACK OLIVES.
AND NOW THEY'RE A LOCAL LEGEND
FOR PIZZA WAUKEGAN STYLE.
THE CRUST IS SO THIN,
AND THE INGREDIENTS
JUST TASTE FRESH.
PIZZA'S IT FOR ME.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
PIZZA SAUCE...
WE ARE.
EXTRA-HEAVY PIZZA SAUCE
WITH BASIL.
I CHANGE IT UP A LITTLE BIT
BY ADDING CRUSHED TOMATOES.
IT GIVES IT A LITTLE BIT
MORE FLAVOR.
OKAY...
WATER?
THIN IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
NOW IN WITH THE WHISK.
CORRECT. NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
THAT'S A LITTLE.
A LITTLE BIT. SALT AND SUGAR
TO SWEETEN IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
PUT A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER
IN HERE.
SO REALLY,
THAT'S ALL THE GRANULATED
GARLIC GOES INTO THIS?
IF YOU WANT A LOT
OF GARLIC FLAVOR,
WE'RE GONNA PUT FRESH GARLIC
DOWN IN IT FOR YOU,
AND YOU'RE GONNA BE
SATISFIED.
WOW, YOU SEEM
KIND OF UPPITY ABOUT IT.
SWEET BASIL,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER
I N HERE...
A LITTLE OREGANO.
GREEK OREGANO.
SO WE DON'T COOK THIS?
WE DON'T HEAT THIS UP,
NOTHING?
NO, WE HEAT OUR MARINARA
THAT WE PUT ON SPAGHETTI,
BUT OUR PIZZA SAUCE
IS A COLD PRODUCT.
STAY!
THIS IS OUR PIZZA DOUGH.
LOOK AT THESE BAD BOYS.
THAT'S NICE.
IT'S A FAMILY RECIPE,
MADE FRESH EVERY DAY.
NOW YOU RUN A SHEETER, GIVES
YOU REAL GOOD CONSISTENCY.
YES, SIR.
A LITTLE FLOUR ON HERE
SO IT SLIDES THROUGH THE ROLLER.
IT'S A 2-STAGE ROLLER,
SO THIS IS THE FIRST STAGE.
DUST IT WITH A LITTLE MORE
FLOUR--ABOUT TWO PASSES.
THE FIRST ONE GOES THROUGH,
AND THEN THE SECOND ONE
MAKES IT JUST RIGHT.
THAT'S A PERFECT CONDITION.
NICE AND THIN,
AND THEN YOU'LL
JUST TRIM IT OUT.
YES, SIR.
I LIKE THAT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE SAUCE HERE.
I MEAN, THAT IS SOME THIN CRUST.
I MEAN, THAT RIGHT THERE
I COULD READ THE PAPER THROUGH.
I LIKE IT.
SO THE MEAT GOES DOWN FIRST.
YES.
SO THIS HAS GOT SAUSAGE.
IT'S GOT THE PORK BUTT,
THE ANGUS BEEF.
WE SPICE IT OURSELVES.
WITH SALT, PEPPER, GARLIC,
FENNEL AND CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE CHEESE ON HERE.
THIS IS WISCONSIN CHEESE.
IT MAKES THE BEST PIZZA.
WE'RE GONNA
TAKE SOME ONIONS.
WE'RE GONNA SPRINKLE 'EM
OVER HERE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE GREEN PEPPER ON TOP.
MY UNCLE SAM
USED TO CALL THIS,
(deep voice) "GIMME ONE A THEM
GARBAGE PIZZAS,
EVERYTHING ON THE PIZZA."
SCARE ME IF I WAS A KID.
(normal voice)
OKAY, IN THE OVEN--
HOW HOT'S THAT OVEN?
THAT OVEN IS 450 DEGREES.
IT'S ONLY GONNA TAKE
ABOUT 12 OR 15 MINUTES.
IS IT READY?
LET'S GO. GOOD.
WOW.
AND WHAT DID YOU THROW
THAT ON, A LITTLE CORNMEAL?
TO MAKE IT ROLL
OFF THE BOARD THERE.
WHOA! WHAT IS THAT?
THAT'S A KNIFE.
OH, THERE'S CHICAGO FOR YOU--
CUT INTO SQUARES.
THIS IS CALLED
A CHICAGO BOX CUT.
GUY, ENJOY.
WOW. THAT'S EXACTLY
HOW I LIKE MY PIZZA.
AND LOOK HOW WELL IT HOLDS UP.
THE HOMEMADE SAUSAGE MAKES IT.
AND THEN THE THIN-SLICED ONIONS
AND PEPPERS--
THEY KIND OF MELT INTO IT.
BROTHER, I'M GONNA TELL YOU,
THAT'S SOME MONEY PIE
RIGHT THERE.
IT'S A PLEASURE
TO HAVE YOU HERE, GUY.
(with mouth full)
THAT IS AWESOME.
I CAN'T GET IT
IN MY MOUTH FAST ENOUGH.
THE CRUST IS REALLY CRISPY.
IT'S GREAT.
THE SAUSAGE IS FANTASTIC.
THIS IS ONE OF THE BEST PIZZAS
I'VE EVER HAD.
PEOPLE DIDN'T THINK YOU COULD
SELL FOOD OUT OF A TAVERN.
IT WAS A NOVEL CONCEPT
HERE IN DALLAS.
NOT ANYMORE.
HERE'S YOUR STEAK. WE HAD TO
CREATE A MENU TO DRAW PEOPLE IN.
FROM BAR FOOD
TO REAL FOOD.
THE SALMON, THE STEAKS,
THE CHOPS--IT'S A FAMILY PLACE.
I MEAN, WHEN YOU COME IN HERE,
YOU'RE ONE OF THE FAMILY.
GOOD TO SEE
YOU GUYS AGAIN.
IT'S SO GREAT.
I'M ON THE LASAGNA LIST,
SO WHENEVER THEY MAKE LASAGNA,
THEY GIVE ME A CALL.
OR YOU MIGHT EVEN GET A BURGER
NAMED AFTER YOU.
WHAT'S THE NUMBER ONE BURGER
THAT YOU MAKE?
IT'S CALLED THE "DON."
YOU'RE THE DON.
ME.
DON HAD SOME IDEAS,
PUT ON THE MENU THE NEXT DAY.
WE HAVEN'T LOOKED BACK.
HOW DO WE GET STARTED?
FRESH-GROUND
ANGUS BEEF.
FRESH-GROUND--
THE ONLY WAY TO GO.
HERE'S OUR
LITTLE SECRET HERE.
THERE'S OUR LITTLE MARINADE
THAT WE PUT ON.
WHAT DO WE GOT
IN THERE?
A LITTLE SOY,
A LITTLE GARLIC.
AND A FEW OTHER THINGS.
OKAY, I WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE?
NO.
REALLY?
WHO TAUGHT YOU
THIS LITTLE TRICK?
SOME GUY.
THE BACK EAST IS
COMIN' OUT OF THE DALLAS BOY
RIGHT NOW--"SOME GUY."
WE GRAB A LITTLE ONION,
A LITTLE PAPRIKA ON TOP,
JUST TO SPARKLE 'EM UP.
DID YOU JUST SAY
"SPARKLE"?
SPICE 'EM UP,
SPARKLE...
DID YOU SAY
"SPARKLE"?
I-I DON'T KNOW WHAT I SAID.
I HAVE NO IDEA.
DID YOU SAY
"SPARKLE 'EM UP"?
SO WE PUT A LITTLE MORE
SAUCE ON IT.
I'M THE SAUCE-INATOR.
THERE YOU GO. A LITTLE
RYE BREAD, TOASTED.
DUST HER AGAIN, ONE LAST TIME.
ADD SOME SWISS CHEESE.
PUT A LITTLE BACON
ON HERE.
ONE PIECE?
ONE PIECE--WELL,
YOU CAN GET EXTRA.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A COUPLE
JALAPEÑOS ON IT. THAT'S DONE.
(whistles)
WHICH ONE'S GUIDO?
MEDIUM-RARE--WOW.
THIS SAUCE THAT YOU HAVE
BASTED THIS IN
REALLY COMPLEMENTS IT NICE.
THANK YOU.
THAT IS SUPER-MONDO JUICY.
HERE'S THE KICKER--
THE FRESH-GROUND ANGUS,
IT'S STEAK-LIKE.
AWESOME, BROTHER.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
GOSH!
I RECOMMEND THE DON.
THE FOOD THAT CHRIS COOKS
IS PHENOMENAL.
AND SOMETIMES IT'S WHATEVER
HE FEELS LIKE MAKING.
GOT A LITTLE
MULLIGATAWNY SOUP HERE.
HAVE YOU TRIED
THE MUGGA-WUGGA-WUGGA SOUP?
"MULLIGATAWNY."
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM. BIG FLAVOR.
♪♪
THE SAUSAGE,
GREEN OLIVE...
AT LOUIE'S
IN DALLAS, TEXAS...
YOUR FOLKS KNOW
YOU'RE OUT?
LOUIE CANELAKES
AND HIS BROTHER CHRIS...
(Chris) MEDIUM RARE.
ARE PROUD TO BE
RUNNIN' A JOINT
THAT ISN'T KNOWN
FOR ITS CURB APPEAL.
HALF THE TIME, PEOPLE DRIVE
BY, THEY'RE LIKE, "WHAT?
THAT PLACE SERVES FOOD?"
SURE DOES.
BEST PIZZA
I'VE EVER HAD.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE SANDWICH
HERE, HANDS DOWN.
(Chris) THAT IS SOUVLAKI
WITH MASHED POTATOES.
THEY DO
A HALF CHIPOTLE CHICKEN.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND CHRIS WILL TRY
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
MULLIGATAWNY SOUP.
A TRADITIONAL
INDIAN DISH...
PICK UP SOUP.
CHRIS FIRST HEARD ABOUT ON TV.
POPULARIZED IN A SITCOM SERIES,
UH, "SEINFELD."
UH, NEWMAN...
YEAH?
"MULLIGATAWNY."
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE CHICKEN STOCK.
SO HOT CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BUTTER,
TAKE SOME ONIONS.
ARE WE LOOKIN' TO CARAMELIZE,
OR ARE WE LOOKIN' TO...
WE'RE JUST...
TO SWEAT 'EM
A LITTLE BIT?
YEAH, WE'RE JUST GONNA
COOK 'EM DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
GONNA GO FIVE, TEN MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE LAMB ON TOP.
LAMB LEG
THAT YOU DICE UP.
THIS WAS--THIS WAS ACTUALLY
A BONELESS LEG OF LAMB.
MY MOTHER MADE ME
TRIM THE FAT OFF THERE,
'CAUSE SHE DOESN'T LIKE
A LOT OF FAT IN THERE.
WE GOT A LITTLE GROUND CUMIN,
CORIANDER, BLACK PEPPER,
TURMERIC AND GROUND NUTMEG,
AND THIS IS GROUND CLOVES.
TAKE A COUPLE JALAPEÑOS.
SEEDS, RIBS, EVERYTHING.
WELL, WE'RE IN TEXAS.
WE LIKE SPICY.
SOME GARLIC--
THERE'S GINGER ROOT, GRATED.
(mouths words)
SO DID YOU GUYS
GET ALL THAT?
RIGHT ON
WITH THE SPICES.
COOK THIS DOWN
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
SO THE MEAT'S
COOKED DOWN...
YEP.
SMELLS DYNAMITE.
NEXT STEP, WE'RE GONNA START
DRESSIN' IT UP IN THE POT.
WE'RE GONNA...
DRESS IT UP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME POTATOES, SOME PEAS.
APPLES, CARROTS.
I USE A LITTLE PIZZA SAUCE
IN MY RECIPE.
GO!
GONNA BE INTERESTING.
THAT NEEDS TO SIMMER
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS.
REALLY? SIX HOURS.
IF YOU COULD GO LONGER,
THE BETTER.
I CAN'T WAIT TO TRY IT.
ARE WE DONE?
YEAH. ENJOY.
THAT'S THE SPOON I GET.
BIG PORTIONS, SMALL UTENSILS--
WELCOME TO LOUIE'S.
MMM. BIG FLAVOR.
I LIKE THE SPICE.
I LIKE HOW THE LAMB
SHREDS APART. GOOD SOUP.
CAN I KEEP IT
AS A SOUVENIR?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S REALLY NICE.
THINK OF ME.
IT'S JUST REAL SPICY,
AND IT'S GREAT.
REAL FLAVORFUL,
IT'S REALLY NICE.
LOOK UP AND DOWN THE MENU.
I'VE NEVER HAD A BAD MEAL.
IT DOESN'T LOOK THE GREATEST
FROM THE OUTSIDE,
BUT ONCE YOU GET INSIDE,
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
WE POUR A GENEROUS DRINK.
MY BROTHER'S GOT
A GENEROUS HAND WITH THE FOOD.
SPAGHETTI.
IT IS MY FAVORITE SPOT,
HANDS DOWN.
I'M GONNA EAT THIS
WHOLE THING, SERIOUSLY.
YOU CAN HAVE IT. WE'LL
MAKE YOU ANOTHER ONE TO GO.
MMM. PLEASE.
I'LL TAKE IT.
OKAY.
IT'S A DEAL.
RED CONVERTIBLE CAMARO
OUT FRONT.
IT'S STILL THERE, RIGHT?
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
BUT DON'T WORRY,
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) ANYHOW... DID I--
WELCOME TO "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHERE DID THAT HOST GO?
WELCOME TO "DINERS"...
HI. OVER HERE.
I'M HIS STAND-IN.