HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THEY'RE GIVIN' IT LOVE.
BISCUITS, BAGELS AND BLTs.
THIS ISN'T GONNA BE BAD.
IN PORTLAND...
GRIDDLE CAKES.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT...
I LOVE THAT IT'S PART
OF OUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
WHERE A BASIC BREAKFAST...
ENJOY.
MEANS SWEET POTATO BISCUITS...
BEST IN THE COUNTRY,
I WOULD SAY.
AND SICILIAN HASH.
(man) HASH UP.
MMM.
IN SAN ANSELMO, CALIFORNIA...
(man) MUSHROOM OMELET UP.
WHERE DINER COOKIN'...
ALL RIGHT!
IS BACON, LETTUCE
AND SOFT-SHELL CRAB.
IT'S A SUPER
PREMIUM DINER.
THAT'S A NEW ONE.
NICE. MMM. OH, HO.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
OH, HO.
AND IN BOYNTON BEACH,
FLORIDA...
(man) A CORNED BEEF,
PLEASE.
THE REAL-DEAL DELI.
THE BEST REUBEN
I'VE EVER HAD.
AND THIS
IS A ONE-STOP SHOP?
FROM SCRATCH.
FROM MATZO BALLS TO BAGELS...
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
THAT'S WHY I COME HERE.
BY A CREW FROM NEW YORK.
A REUBEN TO GO.
MMM. I JUST CAN'T GET ENOUGH
OF THAT MATZO BALL.
THE MATZO BALL MAD MAN.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO TRIPLE "D" ROLLS INTO TOWN.
WHAT DO WE FIND?
WELL, WE GOT SECTIONS
AND DISTRICTS AND NEIGHBORHOODS.
HERE WE ARE IN PORTLAND, OREGON,
IN THE MT. SCOTT-ARLETA
NEIGHBORHOOD,
WHERE A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
HAVE SET UP SHOP
SERVING UP FAMILY FAVORITES WITH
A LITTLE CULINARY SCHOOL FLAIR.
TIME TO CHECK OUT
ARLETA LIBRARY BAKERY CAFé.
GRIDDLE CAKES.
I JUST LOVE THIS PLACE.
IT'S SUCH
HIGH-QUALITY FOOD.
(man) HASH UP.
THE HASH--I MEAN,
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
BEST BISCUITS IN THE COUNTRY,
I WOULD SAY.
ENJOY.
I LOVE THAT IT'S PART
OF OUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
THANK YOU, HON.
AND THEIRS, TOO.
WE FELT KIND OF UNDERSERVED
HAVING TO GO ACROSS TOWN
TO GET A DECENT
BITE TO EAT.
I'M RIGHT BEHIND.
SO RESTAURANT VETS
NICK IANNARONE
AND HIS WIFE SARAH
DECIDED TO OPEN
A PLACE OF THEIR OWN...
ALREADY WORKIN'.
AND BROUGHT IN
CHEF MATT HOWARD
TO PUT A SPIN
ON THE CLASSICS...
HALF & HALF WITH SOUP.
LIKE SEMOLINA GRIDDLE CAKES...
AMAZING
BEYOND A PANCAKE.
FRENCH TOAST MADE FROM BRIOCHE
AND THIS
WEEKEND BRUNCH SPECIAL...
SICILIAN HASH--
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
SCRATCH-MADE FROM AN ITALIAN
ROLLED BEEF CALLED BRACIOLA.
WE'RE MAKING THE STUFFING
FOR THE BRACIOLA.
BLENDED OIL, ONIONS...
AND SOME GARLIC.
YEP. SEASON IT UP
WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
LOTS OF CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
CAN'T GET ENOUGH
OF THAT.
WE'RE GONNA
ADD OREGANO.
WOW,
THIS IS BIG FLAVOR TIME.
SOME BASIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF THYME.
TWO BAY LEAVES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD BREADCRUMBS.
AND THAT'S GONNA BE THE STUFFING
INSIDE OF THE BRACIOLA.
OR THE SICILIAN HASH.
YOU'RE GONNA START
BY JUST UNROLLING A PIECE
OF INSIDE ROUND.
3/4 OF AN INCH
TO AN INCH.
YES. YOU WANT TO LIBERALLY
COAT IT WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
TAKE OUR STUFFING MIXTURE,
SPREAD THIS MIXTURE ALL OUT.
CHEESE?
PARMESAN CHEESE.
SPREAD THAT ALL OVER THE TOP.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT UP
LIKE THAT,
AND WE'RE
GONNA TRUSS IT.
OH, DOUBLE OVER,
LOOK UNDER.
WHOO-HOO!
THEN YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S NICE AND TIGHT.
SEASON THE OUTSIDE
WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLENDED OLIVE OIL.
AT THIS POINT, WE CAN JUST
GO AHEAD AND POP IT IN.
WE'LL HIT
ALL THE SIDES OF IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
RED WINE--
DO ABOUT A HALF A BOTTLE.
GET RIGHT IN THERE
FOR A FACIAL.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA
LET THAT DEGLAZE.
WE CAN TAKE
OUR CRUSHED TOMATOES...
MMM.
COVER THIS UP, POP IT,
12 HOURS. THAT'S THAT.
PULL IT OUT OF THE BRAISING
LIQUID, LET IT REST.
NOW HAS COME THE TIME
TO GIVE IT A SLICE, CHOP IT UP
AND GET IT READY
FOR THE HASH.
SO IT'S COOLED DOWN COMPLETELY,
SO WHEN WE CUT INTO IT,
IT'S NOT JUST GONNA
START BREAKING APART.
1/2-INCH SECTIONS.
OKAY, GOOD. MMM.
GONNA JUST KIND OF ROUGH-CHOP
THIS A LITTLE BIT.
WE'LL PUT IT
INTO THE MIXING BOWL HERE.
YOU'VE ALREADY PUT MORE TIME
AND ENERGY INTO YOUR HASH
THAN MOST PEOPLE
PUT INTO DINNER.
ADD OUR BRACIOLA
BRAISING LIQUID.
THEN WE'RE
GONNA HIT THAT
WITH A LITTLE FRESH
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER...
OHH.
A GOOD AMOUNT OF SALT,
A LITTLE MIX.
WE CAN TAKE THIS AND GO AHEAD
AND JUST BUILD THE DISH.
A LITTLE BIT
OF INFUSED OREGANO OIL.
YOU CAN PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT DOWN FIRST.
SOME RED POTATOES
THAT HAVE BEEN...
BASICALLY PAR-COOKED.
AND GIVE THAT A PRESS.
SALT. AND EVERY LAYER
WE WANT TO GIVE SEASONING TO.
BLACK PEPPER.
PEPPER GRINDER--
THEY GET A WORKOUT.
SOME PEPPERS AND ONIONS
WE HAVE SWEATED DOWN
WITH SOME SALT, PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT OF BAY LEAF.
ON TOP OF THAT GOES
OUR BRACIOLA MIXTURE.
WE'LL GO AHEAD AND HIT THAT
AGAIN, LIKE I SAID,
WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
SALT AND PEPPER.
CAN'T I JUST GET THAT
CONNECTED TO YOUR ARM?
(laughs)
IT TAKES
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
WE'LL MAKE A PARMESAN EGG
TO TOP IT WITH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE EGG
AND FOLD IT OVER ON ITSELF.
FLIP THE HASH.
IT LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
I WANT A CUP
OF THAT TO GO.
TRANSFER IT TO THE PLATE.
TAKE OUR SOFT
PARMESAN EGG...
WOW.
WITH A LITTLE SLIVER
OF ROASTED PEPPER.
A GARNISH OF FRESH CHOPPED
FLAT-LEAF ITALIAN PARSLEY.
WHOA. YOU'RE DREAMIN'
OF THE STEAMIN'.
MMM. WOW, MAN.
IT HAS MORE COMPLEXITY
THAN I'M NORMALLY USED TO.
YOU HAVE A GREAT RATIO
OF MEAT TO POTATO.
IN THE LAND OF HASH,
IT'S ITS OWN LITTLE STATE.
I'LL HAVE THIS ANYTIME
I COME TO PORTLAND.
MMM. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
BRACIOLA'S KILLER.
THE HASH--
IT'S FANTASTIC.
(woman) IT'S A GOOD
COLLECTION OF FLAVORS.
(Nick) BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
THERE'S NOTHING
PROCESSED.
DESSERT FOR YOU GUYS.
(woman) THEY DO
THEIR OWN BAKING.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
HOW TO BAKE?
I WENT
TO CULINARY SCHOOL,
BUT I REALLY LEARNED
HOW TO BAKE IN KITCHENS.
DID SHE EVER--
FROM SCONES AND MUFFINS
TO COFFEE CAKE DONE
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY...
A COUPLE POUNDS OF BUTTER,
A COUPLE POUNDS OF SUGAR.
AND A FAN FAVORITE...
SARAH'S
SWEET POTATO BISCUITS.
SCRATCH-MADE EVERY DAY.
MMM.
THEY'RE AWESOME.
WHAT ARE WE STARTING WITH?
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THROW SOME BUTTER IN THERE,
BAKING POWDER AND KOSHER SALT.
SECRET INGREDIENT
IS FRESH GRATED NUTMEG.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SPIN.
AND I'M GONNA LET IT GO
TILL THE BUTTER'S PEA-SIZED.
SO THE SWEET POTATOES ARE IN
WITH THEIR SUGARY GOODNESS.
BUTTERMILK. I GET AS MUCH
LIQUID IN THERE AS POSSIBLE.
DON'T OVERMIX
YOUR BISCUITS.
YOU KNOW THIS IF YOU'RE
A BISCUIT MAN, RIGHT?
YEAH. NO, I'M NOT REALLY.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO MAKE THIS TOO THIN,
'CAUSE YOU WANT YOUR BISCUITS
TO BE NICE AND TALL.
NOW WHAT ARE THESE
GONNA BAKE OFF AT?
375.
FOR HOW LONG?
12 TO 15.
THAT'S A LOT OF WORK
JUST FOR A BISCUIT.
AND FOR THE STUFF
THEY'RE SERVING IT WITH--
PORK LOIN BRINED,
SEARED AND ROASTED,
WITH HOMEMADE GRAVY.
ROSEMARY SAUSAGE GRAVY,
BLENDED OIL.
PORK SAUSAGE.
BREAK THIS UP.
THE ONIONS.
RENDER ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
HAND ME THAT FLOUR.
WE'RE GONNA USE THE FAT THAT'S
IN THERE, MAKE A LITTLE ROUX.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ONION POWDER, GARLIC POWDER,
WHITE PEPPER.
THAT'S PERFECT WITH THE THYME.
YOU'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
EH.
SALT AND PEPPER.
BRING IN THE CHICKEN STOCK.
THEN WE GOT
OUR 2 QUARTS OF CREAM.
WHOA.
FRESH CHOPPED ROSEMARY.
COOK THIS FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES
TILL IT THICKENS UP.
(Matt) WE'VE GOT OUR
PORK LOIN THAT HAS CHILLED.
HEAT IT UP.
BISCUITS DONE?
YEP.
TWO SOLDIERS.
PORK LOIN RIGHT ON TOP.
COMPADRES OF PORK.
THAT'S A PORTION OF PIG,
PAL.
GRAVY RIGHT ON TOP OF THERE,
A TOUCH OF PARSLEY.
(chuckles) I THINK
IT'S PRETTY DYNAMITE.
CREAMY AS CAN BE.
YOU GOT SOME PORK LOIN
THAT STANDS ON ITS OWN.
YOU GOT ENOUGH
SAUSAGE IN THERE.
I'D CALL THAT GOURMET
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
IT'S JUST KILLER. THE PORK
IN THERE IS REALLY GOOD.
WHEN IT HITS THE TABLE,
YOU CAN JUST SMELL THE ROSEMARY
OFF THE GRAVY.
HASH.
IT'S GREAT FOOD
EVERY DAY.
WE ALL ENJOY IT
LIKE CRAZY.
YOU DON'T HAVE
A LOT OF TABLES,
BUT PEOPLE SURE
ARE CLAMORING TO GET IN.
THERE'S A LINE OUT THE DOOR
RIGHT NOW.
EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD NEEDS
A LITTLE SPOT LIKE THIS
WHERE THEY CAN COME
AND FEEL COMFORTABLE,
GET A NICE BITE TO EAT.
YOU'RE DOING THIS
TO SUPPORT YOUR COMMUNITY?
YEAH, DEFINITELY.
THAT'S PRETTY DEEP.
UP NEXT...
ORDER UP--
CHICKEN MARSALA.
WE'RE HEADIN' FOR NOR-CAL...
IT'S SPECTACULAR.
WHERE A CLASSICALLY
TRAINED CHEF
IS DOING THE DINER THING
HIS WAY.
THE AHI TUNA POT STICKERS.
MM-HMM. THAT TENDER DOUGH--
IT'S LIKE JUST VELVET.
NOW WHEN I SAY THE NAME BUBBA,
YOU GOTTA THINK
BUBBA GUMP SHRIMP,
YOU GOTTA THINK--YOU PROBABLY
HAD A BUDDY NAMED BUBBA,
JUST FLAT-OUT HUBBA BUBBA.
SO YOU GOTTA STOP AND CHECK OUT
A JOINT CALLED BUBBA'S DINER
HERE IN SAN ANSELMO, CALIFORNIA,
JUST NORTH OF SAN FRAN.
BUT REMEMBER, RULE 206
OF THE TRIPLE "D" CODE--
YOU CAN NEVER JUDGE A MENU
BY ITS NAME.
ORDER UP--CHICKEN MARSALA.
THIS IS FABULOUS.
(man) CRèME BRûLéE
FRENCH TOAST.
THEY'RE GIVIN' IT LOVE.
THE BEST BURGERS
IN THE COUNTY.
IT'S A SUPER
PREMIUM DINER.
THAT'S A NEW ONE.
ORDER IN.
WHERE OWNER AND CHEF
JOHN SARRAN...
MUSHROOM OMELET.
IS MIXING DINER CLASSICS...
FRIES, SHAKES.
THE HASH IS WONDERFUL.
WITH HIS CLASSIC TRAINING
FROM CULINARY SCHOOL.
THE AHI TUNA POT STICKERS.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
FOOD'S A PASSION.
FOR ME, THE THRILL IS REALLY
SEARCHING OUT GREAT INGREDIENTS,
JUST TURN OUT REALLY GOOD
QUALITY FOOD.
JUST AMAZING.
YEAH, LIKE GRILLED
KOBE BEEF MEAT LOAF,
A PORTOBELLO MUSHROOM OMELET
AND GET THIS...
SOFT-SHELL CRAB BLT.
THE BLT's NOT GOOD
ENOUGH BY ITSELF.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE ONE
WITH SOFT-SHELL CRAB.
ABSOLUTELY.
SEASON OUR FLOUR FIRST--
SEA SALT.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF GRANULATED GARLIC
AND OTHER THINGS
IN THERE.
MALABAR ORGANIC
BLACK PEPPER.
GOOD?
I THINK THAT'S GOOD.
DROP 'EM IN, TWO PER ORDER
AND TWO SIDES.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO RIGHT
INTO SOME ORGANIC BUTTERMILK.
AND THEN MORE FLOUR
STICKS TO THE BUTTERMILK.
WE'RE USING CAKE FLOUR
FOR FRYING.
'CAUSE CAKE FLOUR ALMOST
HAS NO GLUTEN TO IT,
SO IT'S NICE AND LIGHT.
AND THEN SLOWLY
DROP THAT IN.
DREDGE 'EM DOWN IN.
SOME APPLEWOOD
SMOKED BACON.
ORGANIC SOURDOUGH BREAD.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE A SLICE
THROUGH THE HEIRLOOM TOMATO.
LOOK AT HOW BEAUTIFUL
THAT IS.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR CRABS
AND DRAIN 'EM RIGHT AWAY,
'CAUSE OIL ON THE SURFACE
WILL GO FROM CRISPY TO SOGGY
IN JUST A SECOND.
TAKE OUR BACON.
THIS ISN'T GONNA BE BAD,
I CAN TELL YA.
WE USE GARLIC-BASIL AIOLI THAT
WE MAKE HERE, ROASTED GARLIC.
WE USE THAI BASIL.
I THINK THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
SWEETER NOTE TO IT.
A COUPLE NICE PIECES OF TOMATO,
ORGANIC LETTUCE,
BACON, THESE CRABS.
AND THERE WILL BE A TRASH
COMPACTOR TO SMUSH IT DOWN...
(imitating trash compactor)
SO I CAN GET IT
IN MY FACE.
CRAB CLAWS--
THEY'RE GONNA BE OUR "GARNY."
AND WE'RE GONNA PART THIS
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
NICE.
OH, HO.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU.
THE CRUNCH IS PERFECT.
THE HEIRLOOM TOMATO
IS SO NICE AND SWEET.
NOW I'VE MADE
A LOT OF BLTs.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER
PUT SOFT-SHELL CRAB IN IT,
BUT I CAN TELL YOU THAT
THE PICTURE'S CHANGED.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
KEEP AN EYE ON THIS GUY.
THE COMBINATION IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S SPECTACULAR.
EVEN THE BASIC STUFF HERE
IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
(John) MUSHROOM OMELET UP.
CRèME BRûLéE FRENCH TOAST--
WHO'S GOT THAT?
(woman) THE AHI TUNA
POT STICKER.
WE REPRESENT
THE CLASSICAL DINER FARE
SO SOMETHING, LIKE, UH,
OUT THERE ON THE EDGE.
AHI POT STICKERS--
A BIT OUT ON THE EDGE.
THOSE POT STICKERS--
NOBODY CAN BEAT THAT.
SO LET'S GET THIS GOING.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS SUSHI-GRADE AHI.
THIS IS NUMBER ONE, BABY.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
GOOD-BYE-FINGERTIP CHOPPING.
WHERE THIS LOOKS LIKE
I'M JUST CHOPPING,
IT IS REALLY PASSING
THROUGH THE FISH IN A NICE WAY
THAT'S KEEPING A LOT
OF THE CELL STRUCTURE INTACT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THIS
INTO THE BOWL.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE TRINITY.
THE TRINITY
IN JAPANESE COOKING.
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC,
GINGER, GREEN ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT MORE HERE.
OKAY.
AND THEN MIRIN.
JAPANESE COOKING WINE--
A LITTLE BIT SWEET.
RICE WINE.
CORNSTARCH TO TIGHTEN.
CORNSTARCH. WE'RE GONNA DO
A LITTLE BIT OF EGG WHITE.
MIX THIS ALL UP WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF SOY SAUCE.
MY MOUTH'S
STARTING TO WATER.
WE REALLY WANT
THE TUNA TO SHINE.
THOROUGHLY
COMBINE THERE.
OUR SAUCE
IS VERY SIMPLE.
WELL, AND THAT'S A REAL
JAPANESE PHILOSOPHY ABOUT FOOD
IS LESS IS MORE.
START OFF
WITH GREAT INGREDIENTS,
USE 'EM THE RIGHT WAY,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO DOCTOR 'EM
WITH A BUNCH OF EXTRA STUFF.
SO THIS IS GONNA
BE THE DIPPING SAUCE.
SO I ASSUME A LITTLE RICE WINE
VINEGAR, SOME SOY SAUCE
AND SOME SESAME OIL?
AMEN, BROTHER.
YOU GOT IT.
FANTASTIC. ARE WE MAKING
THE PASTA FOR THAT, TOO?
WE ARE.
OHH, LOVE THAT.
WE'RE GONNA
MIX CAKE FLOUR...
WHAT WAS THE OTHER FLOUR
YOU'RE POPPING IN?
ALL-PURPOSE.
WE'RE GONNA CRACK SOME ORGANIC
BROWN EGGS INTO THE WATER.
WE'RE GONNA GIVE IT
JUST A NICE MIX,
AND WE'RE GONNA FLAVOR IT
WITH SOME SEA SALT--
ALWAYS SEASONING.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WE DON'T HAVE
TO MIX THIS BY--OH. OH!
OH, NO. COME ON.
SO THE FLOUR
JUST GOES IN.
WE'RE GONNA TURN IT ON
FOR A SECOND.
GONNA GO BACK AND FORTH SLOWLY
TO MIX IN THE WET.
TAKE A LOOK. WE WANT TO MAKE
SURE IT'S CLUMPING TOGETHER.
CRAZY HOW YOU CAN
JUST TOUCH IT
AND GET AN IDEA
OF WHERE HE'S AT.
THESE ARE TRADITIONAL
ITALIAN BRASS DIES
THAT'LL GIVE SURFACE ABRASIONS
THAT'LL HOLD THE SAUCE.
KIND OF GIVES YOU THAT LITTLE
BIT OF DUSTY, RAW FEEL.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA FEED IT
ONTO THE SPINDLE HERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA
COLLECT IT.
ANYBODY ELSE AT HOME
TRIPPIN' OUT?
THIS IS CRAZY. IT'S LIKE
CULINARY DISNEYLAND.
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHERE YOU WANT IT TO BE--
SLIGHTLY ABOVE
BODY TEMPERATURE.
SO WE'RE DONE?
WE'RE DONE.
IF WE DON'T WORK WITH THIS
QUICKLY, IT WILL DRY OUT.
SO WE'RE GONNA USE NATURE'S
BALL BEARINGS HERE,
AND IT'S RICE FLOUR,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
CUT THAT DOWN INTO SHEETS,
AND I'M JUST GONNA STACK IT UP
IN A CUT DEAL, LIKE SO.
WE'LL JUST
SET THESE ASIDE.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA WET THE TWO SIDES
OF THE PASTA, SOME FILLING,
GONNA BRING IT TOGETHER,
GONNA MAKE SURE THE SIDES
ARE REALLY WELL PINCHED.
PLEAT IT. AND WE HAVE
AN AHI TUNA POT STICKER.
WE LOAD 'EM ALL UP.
TAKE 'EM TO THE KITCHEN.
LOAD 'EM ALL UP.
NOW THEY'RE GONNA
GO TO BOILING WATER.
THEY'RE GONNA GO
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
WHEN THEY START FLOATING,
THEY'RE TYPICALLY DONE.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME
ORGANIC CLARIFIED BUTTER.
IT JUST GIVES IT
A LITTLE BIT OF BROWNING.
LET 'EM STEAM.
OH, ONE GOT AWAY.
HA-YA, WHOO, AH-AH.
ORGANIC BABY SPINACH,
FRIED GARLIC.
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT A NICE
CRUNCH AND SOME FLAVOR.
STANDARD DINER FARE
RIGHT HERE AT BUBBA'S.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO AHEAD
AND PLATE 'EM RIGHT UP.
I THINK THAT'S THE ONE.
CHOPSTICKS.
(chuckles)
THAT TENDER DOUGH--
IT'S LIKE JUST VELVET.
UP THERE IN SOME OF THE BEST
POT STICKERS I'VE EVER HAD.
THANK YOU.
IT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT'S MOST POPULAR FOR US
AND ONE OF THE THINGS,
FRANKLY, I'M MOST PROUD OF.
YOU ABSOLUTELY
SHOULD BE.
BUT YOU'VE JUST COMPLETELY MADE
A MESS OF THINGS FOR ME NOW,
BECAUSE THAT DOUGH
IS OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
TASTING GINGER AND GARLIC,
AND IT'S NICE AND LIGHT.
(John) ALL RIGHT.
FANTASTIC FOOD,
INTERESTING MENU,
NOT SOMETHING
YOU'D EXPECT.
(John) CRISPY THAI SALAD UP.
EVERYTHING'S COOKED WITH LOVE.
(John) CHANTERELLES.
SCRATCH-MAKING THINGS, TONS
OF TIME AND ATTENTION TO IT.
BARBECUED RIBS.
THEY COME THROUGH THE DOORS.
WE WIN 'EM OVER
AS FRIENDS.
THEY KNOW WHAT WE'RE ALL ABOUT--
JUST GOOD WHOLESOME FOOD.
YOU COULD RUN FOR SOME TYPE
OF POLITICAL OFFICE
AFTER WHAT
YOU'VE DONE HERE.
THANKS, BROTHER.
I HAD A GREAT TIME.
NEXT STOP...
REUBEN TO GO.
SOUTHERN FLORIDA.
EVERYTHING YOU GET HERE
IS JUST GREAT.
FOR A TASTE OF NEW YORK.
THEIR MATZO BALL SOUP
IS THE BOMB.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
THESE ARE GONNA COOK
FOR ABOUT
15 TO 17 MINUTES.
EVERYBODY AT HOME
IS ASKING THE SAME QUESTION--
"ARE THEY FLOATING?"
YOU KNOW, DINERS
COME IN EVERY SHAPE OR SIZE.
I THINK WE'VE SEEN THAT
AS WE'VE TOURED THE COUNTRY
HERE ON TRIPLE "D."
YOU GET YOUR FREESTANDING
TO ONES THAT ARE IN STRIP MALLS.
WELL, TODAY,
I'M AT A COMBO JOINT,
A DINER, BAKERY, DELI
HERE IN BOYNTON BEACH
IN SOUTH FLORIDA.
NOW IT MAY BE IN SOUTH FLORIDA,
BUT THEIR ROOTS COME
FROM UP NORTH IN NEW YORK CITY.
TIME WE CHECK OUT FLAKOWITZ.
(man) PICK UP
A CORNED BEEF, PLEASE.
SO EVERYBODY LOVES IT.
EVERYBODY LOVES IT.
(man) BRISKET DINNER
PICK UP.
THIS IS THE GOOD STUFF.
A FULL-SERVICE DELI...
DOUBLE POTATO SALAD.
AND BAKERY.
THEIR CHOCOLATE BABKA
IS VERY GOOD.
ALL THEIR PASTRIES ARE GOOD,
AND THIS IS THE ONLY GAME
IN TOWN.
THANKS TO NEW YORK FOOD BIZ
VETS ROBERT PIROZZI...
REUBEN TO GO.
HIS DAD ANGELO,
WHO DOES THE BAKING...
BAGELS, THE BABKA.
AND DOMINICK LoCASTROH...
BRATWURST, DOUBLE FRIES.
SERVIN' UP ALL THE CLASSICS.
I ALWAYS ORDER
THE CORNED BEEF.
THE BREAD-TO-MEAT
RATIO...
THEIR MATZO BALL SOUP
IS THE BOMB.
MY MOTHER
USED TO MAKE THAT.
IT'S MATZO BALL TIME.
MATZO BALL TIME.
SO THIS IS MATZO MEAL.
WATCH YOUR FACE. THERE'S
GONNA BE A LITTLE POWDER.
AND NOW WE JUST...
ARE YOU THERE,
UNCLE DOMINICK?
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BAKING POWDER...
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER.
SOUP BASE.
CHICKEN STOCK.
I HAVE 40 EGGS HERE.
THIS IS A BUTTER-AND-OIL MIX.
I'D LIKE TO HAVE
A SHOT OF THAT.
THAT'LL WAKE YOU UP
IN THE MORNING.
WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME WATER.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA MIX
THIS UP A LITTLE BIT RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S WHAT
THE BARBECUE FORK'S FOR.
I JUST GO
RIGHT IN THERE.
MATZO BALLS ARE REALLY,
REALLY FICKLE.
IF IT'S NOT RIGHT,
THEY'RE SINKERS.
HOW DO WE KEEP THAT
FROM HAPPENING?
IT'S A LOT
OF TRIAL AND ERROR.
THIS HAS BEEN SITTIN' IN OUR
WALK-IN FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS.
WE'LL JUST PUT A LITTLE OIL
ON HERE SO IT DOESN'T STICK.
I LIKE THE JOB YOU GIVE
THE GUY FROM CALIFORNIA...
YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
GREASE THE PAN,
DONNIE.
JUST GO
RIGHT ALONG HERE.
PRETTY UNIFORM.
YEAH, WELL, WE TRY.
PICK 'EM UP LIKE THIS
AND GIVE 'EM THAT?
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY MATZO BALLS
WE GO THROUGH AT PASSOVER?
5,000?
ABOUT 7,000.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
THESE ARE GONNA COOK
FOR ABOUT
15 TO 17 MINUTES.
NOW ARE THEY READY TO EAT
WHEN THEY COME OUT?
ABSOLUTELY.
EVERYBODY AT HOME IS ASKING
THE SAME QUESTION--
"ARE THEY FLOATING?" AND THEY
FLOAT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
SO NOW WE PULL 'EM,
PUT 'EM IN THE ICE BATH.
READY FOR THE SOUP.
CHICKEN IN THE POT.
THIS IS NOT
JUST FOR ONE PERSON.
IT'S FOR ONE PERSON.
REALLY?
MMM. WOW,
THAT'S NICE AND TENDER.
I LOVE CHICKEN
AND DUMPLINGS.
THIS IS, I GUESS, THE...
IT'S THE JEWISH VERSION.
MMM, THE FLAVOR
IS OUTSTANDING.
I JUST CAN'T GET ENOUGH
OF THAT MATZO BALL, MAN.
GOOD, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE ENJOYING IT.
THE MATZO BALL MAD MAN.
THAT'S IT.
THEY'RE FLUFFY,
AND THEY'RE FANTASTIC.
THE WAY IT'S MADE--DELICIOUS.
NOW YOU'RE HAVING
MATZO BALL--
SOMEBODY'S REALLY
ENJOYING MATZO BALL.
THEIR DAD
MUST BE A BIG EATER.
(laughter)
THEY'RE BIG, THEY'RE FLUFFY.
THE FOOD IS JUST AS GOOD
AS WE GET UP NORTH.
AND THE MENU'S JUST AS BIG.
BRISKET DINNER UP.
SEEDED RYE WITH PASTRAMI
AND CORN BEEF.
THE BEST REUBEN I'VE EVER HAD.
MMM.
NOT JUST THE SANDWICHES,
BUT THE BAKERY IS AWESOME.
PUMPERNICKEL--
DO YOU WANT THE WHOLE LOAF?
THE RUGALACH ARE DELICIOUS.
THE 7-LAYER
IS A GREAT CHOICE.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH AND DINNER--
IT'S JUST ALL GOOD.
THIS IS A ONE-STOP SHOP.
YOU GUYS ARE MAKING OVER
200 YOUR-RECIPE ITEMS HERE.
FROM SCRATCH.
LIKE ROMANIAN STEAK
WITH MUSHROOMS AND ONIONS...
GOOD FLAVOR TO IT.
BRAISED LAMB SHANKS...
DELICIOUS.
AND THIS CLASSIC.
(woman) THE STUFFED CABBAGE
IS OUTSTANDING.
STUFFED WITH BEEF AND RICE
AND TOPPED
WITH SWEET-AND-SOUR SAUCE.
I SEE THE CAST OF CHARACTERS
ARE OUT HERE.
80/20 GROUND BEEF,
SOME OF THE LIQUID CHICKEN.
SAUTéED ONIONS.
I LIKE THAT. IT LOOKS LIKE
THEY'RE ALMOST CARAMELIZED.
YEAH, THEY ARE.
KNEAD THIS IN HERE.
COOKED RICE.
DO A LITTLE
CHICKEN STOCK IN IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S WHERE I SEE A LITTLE BIT
OF YELLOW COMING IN.
YES, SIR. BROWN SUGAR.
THAT'S THE ONE THAT I THINK
SURPRISES ME THE MOST.
IT'S GOTTA
BE A LITTLE SWEET.
SALT.
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER.
SO WE GOT THIS
ALL MIXED UP.
WE'RE GONNA DO OUR
4-OUNCE SCOOPS RIGHT ACROSS.
SO WE'RE DONE WITH THAT.
I'M DONE WITH THAT GUY.
NOW TELL ME THE STORY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE CABBAGE.
WE ACTUALLY STICK IT
IN THE FREEZER FOR A DAY,
BOIL IT
AFTER WE FREEZE IT.
WELL, IF YOU CAN'T
GET IT TENDER THAT WAY,
THEN THERE'S NO WAY
TO GET IT TENDER.
WE'RE GONNA
CORE THIS OUT.
LOOK AT THAT--
CABBAGE BLING.
I USE THE OUTER LEAVES
TO LINE THE BOTTOM OF THE PAN,
SO IT DOESN'T BROWN
WHEN WE COOK IT.
LAY A LITTLE BASE DOWN.
NOW WHAT'S
CABBAGE SAUCE?
TOMATO PURéE,
CARROTS, CELERY, ONIONS,
BROWN SUGAR,
RED WINE VINEGAR, LEMON JUICE,
TWO FRESH LEMONS.
GONNA MAKE A SLURRY.
WITH CORNSTARCH--
YOU TIGHTEN IT UP.
ALL RIGHT, SO WHAT WE DO NOW
IS WE GET A LEAF...
OVER.
LIKE THIS, OVER.
OVER. LAY IT DOWN IN.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BIT MORE SAUCE ON TOP,
CABBAGE, PARCHMENT PAPER.
ALUMINUM FOIL,
SO IT KEEPS THE STEAM IN.
WE SERVE IT UP. AND DO WE PUT
A LITTLE CABBAGE SAUCE ON THAT?
CABBAGE SAUCE
RIGHT ON TOP.
ARE YOU OKAY?
I STARTED TO DROOL.
IT LOOKS GOOD, HUH?
MMM.
PRETTY GOOD FLAVOR.
PRETTY GOOD FLAVOR?
GREAT FLAVOR.
SEE, I LIKE MINE
WITH A LITTLE LEMON.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SHOT
OF LEMON. TASTE IT.
WITHOUT QUESTION.
YOU CAN'T LET IT GO OUT
WITHOUT LEMON ON IT.
JUST KIND OF
BRINGS IT ALL TOGETHER.
PACKAGE DEAL.
KILLER, MAN. REALLY NICE.
STUFFED CABBAGE IS FANTASTIC.
IT'S LIKE A SWEET-AND-SOUR
TASTE--VERY, VERY GOOD.
BIG ENOUGH PORTION?
OH, BOY.
I'M HERE TO EAT.
AT LEAST ONCE
OR TWICE A WEEK.
YOU BET.
ESPECIALLY ON FRIDAYS...
WE WANT TWO KNISHES.
WHEN ANGELO, THE 75-YEAR-OLD
BAKER FROM THE BRONX,
IS THROWIN' DOWN
HIS FAMOUS POTATO KNISH...
THIS IS ALL READY
TO GO IN THE OVEN.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
PICK UP A CORNED BEEF.
AT FLAKOWITZ
IN BOYNTON BEACH, FLORIDA...
(man) MATZO BALL SOUP.
THEY'RE DOING THE DELI THING
THE NEW YORK WAY.
(man) WE HAVE
THE STUFFED CABBAGE.
EVERYTHING YOU GET HERE
IS JUST GREAT.
IT'S THE REAL DEAL?
IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
SO'S THIS GUY...
IT'S QUITE A BUSY SHOP.
ANGELO PIROZZI,
WHO'S BAKING EVERYTHING,
FROM BAGELS TO BABKAS.
WE MAKE ABOUT
30 VARIETIES OF COOKIES.
AND ONLY ON FRIDAY,
HIS FAMOUS POTATO KNISH.
IT'S FLAKY. DELICIOUS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE KNISHES.
THIS IS PREBOILED.
I'M GONNA START CHOPPIN' 'EM
INTO LITTLE SECTIONS.
AND WE'RE LEAVIN'
THE SKINS ON?
YES, THAT'S VERY HEALTHY.
YOU ADD THE ONIONS TO IT.
THIS IS THE WHITE PEPPER.
GARLIC.
I CALL THAT VITAMIN "G."
YEAH, OKAY.
AND THIS IS THE SALT.
"ALL RIGHT, BE QUIET"--
I HEARD YA.
(chuckles)
NOW THIS IS THE BUTTER.
I'M NOT GONNA PUT ALL OF IT IN.
I'M GONNA CUBE THIS UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I DIDN'T THINK WE WERE
PUTTING IT ALL IN.
WE MIGHT AS WELL.
MIX IT ALL UP.
WHAT TEMPERATURE IS THIS
GONNA BE IN THE OVEN?
UH, ABOUT 350.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE POTATO MIXTURE...
INTO THE MIXER.
RIGHT. WE PUT
THE SOUR CREAM IN.
BY THE HANDFUL.
SO ARE WE DONE NOW?
YEAH, THIS IS DONE.
GET MIXED ENOUGH?
ONE, TWO, THREE, AND GO.
WELL, WE HAVE TO DO IT
TOGETHER, THOUGH.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO.
THREE, GO.
OKAY. SEE?
YOU'RE LUCKY
I'M HERE TODAY.
YEAH, I NEED YOU.
I REALLY FELT
THE SINCERITY IN THAT ONE.
I'M GONNA TAKE ONE PIECE
OF PHYLLO DOUGH AT A TIME,
COAT IT WITH BUTTER,
FOLD IT,
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
PUT A NICE GLOB IN THERE.
DID YOU SAY "GLOB"?
(chuckles)
I LIKE THAT.
OKAY, LET ME JUMP IN HERE.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD. SHOULD
WE SIGN 'EM UP, OR WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
BEAUTIFUL, GUY.
AND THEN
I WASH IT WITH EGGS.
SO IT GETS A NICE SHEEN.
RIGHT.
YOU PUT ON EGG WASH
LIKE I PAINT FENCE.
IT'LL GO IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TROUBLE
EATIN' ALL THOSE.
IS THERE A METHOD
OF EATING IT?
TRY IT
WITH A LITTLE MUSTARD.
MMM, DELICIOUS.
THE PHYLLO DOUGH
IS GREAT.
UH-HUH.
IT'S LIGHT. THE POTATO
IS NICE AND HOT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE?
YOU LEFT THE SKINS ON,
AND YOU ROASTED IT,
SO IT KIND OF
GIVES SOME COLOR.
MMM. BUT YOU'RE RIGHT,
BUDDY, THE MUSTARD...
I HAVEN'T HAD A LOT OF KNISHES,
BUT THE ONES I'VE HAD
DO NOT COMPARE TO THAT.
OH, THANK YOU.
AND THE STUFFING
IS REALLY EXCELLENT.
NICE. IT'S LIGHT, FLAKY.
DELICIOUS.
MEAT LOAF'S
IN THE WINDOW.
I'VE NEVER,
NEVER HAD A BAD MEAL.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
GOOD JOB, FELLAS.
IT'S A BIG FAMILY OPERATION,
THOUGH. IT REALLY IS.
(Angelo)
AND EVERYBODY KNOWS YA.
WE'RE FLAKOWITZ PEOPLE.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
YOU DID A VERY NICE JOB
ON THAT.
WELL, YOU DID A GOOD JOB.
I'M SURPRISED
THAT YOU DID IT VERY WELL.
I FIGURED THAT.
PLEASURE MEETING YOU.
YOU'RE A FANTASTIC MAN.
WELL, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
AT AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
...IN YOUR--YOUR SPORTS CAR
AND LEAVE?
NO, NO.
I'M JUST GONNA
HAVE A CUP OF COFFEE.
JUST GONNA GO OVER THERE
OUT OF CAMERA AGAIN...
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND JUST LEAVE ME, AND THEN
COME BACK IN WITH SCISSORS.
HE SHAKES
MY HAND AGAIN.