HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
ALL KINDS OF CLASSICS...
THIS IS THE PERFECT BITE.
MMM.
IN FORT WORTH...
YA-HEE!
WHERE A COWBOY CHEF IS CARRYING
ON A FAMILY LEGACY...
YOU COOK WITH LOVE.
WITH GREEN CHILI STEW...
NICE AND CREAMY. MMM.
I LOVE IT.
AND SERIOUS STEAK EVEN
MARTIN SHEEN'S CHECKING OUT.
MMM. VERY GOOD
AND A LITTLE SPICY.
IN SOUTH FLORIDA...
HERE'S YOUR SMOKED SAMPLER.
THE SHACK IN THE PARK...
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
WHERE THE FISH...
EVERYTHING HERE IS FRESH.
IS SMOKING.
WOW. CREAMY. SOFT. SMOKY.
YOU GOT TO TAKE A BITE
OF THAT.
AND IN PORTLAND...
THE PLACE IS GREAT.
IT'S NOT JUST BACON AND EGGS.
THE BREAKFAST
AND LUNCH JOINT...
HOW Y'ALL DOING?
WHERE THEY'RE DOING THINGS
SOUTHERN-STYLE...
I GOT SOME GRAVY COMING.
AND THAT MEANS BISCUITS...
THE BEST BISCUIT EVER.
WITH THE WORKS.
HOW DO YOU AROUND
ON THAT ONE?
DON'T BE SHY.
I AIN'T THAT KIND OF GUY.
MMM. I FEEL LIKE
I JUST CHUGGED MY BREAKFAST.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
WE HAVE BEEN ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
WE'VE MET ALL KINDS OF CHEFS.
I'VE MET DINER CHEFS,
CULINARY-TRAINED CHEFS.
WE'VE EVEN MET
SELF-TAUGHT CHEFS.
BUT ON TRIPLE "D,"
THIS MIGHT BE THE FIRST TIME
WE'VE MET A COWBOY CHEF HERE
AT FRED'S TEXAS IN FORT WORTH.
YA-HEE!
YOU CANNOT GET A BETTER
16-OUNCE RIB EYE ANYWHERE
IN THE UNITED STATES THAN
RIGHT HERE AT THIS LITTLE JOINT.
I HAD THE LAMB STEW.
WONDERFUL.
HOMEMADE BALSAMIC VINAIGRETTE,
HOMEMADE SALSA.
THE BEST BURGER IN TOWN.
DOES IT SAY "OUTLAW CHEF"?
THAT IT DOES.
IT'S ALL TERRY.
IT'S HIS EXPERIENCE,
HIS PASSION FOR FOOD.
THAT'D BE THE OWNER
TERRY CHANDLER.
I GOT A GREEN CHILI,
NUMBER THREE.
YEAH, TERRY.
FRED WAS THE FAMILY DOG HIS
PARENTS NAMED THE JOINT AFTER
WHEN THEY OPENED 30 YEARS AGO.
IT WAS A GREASY SPOON DINER,
FAMILY-TYPE FOOD.
WHEN THIS TEXAN
CHUCK WAGON CHEF TOOK OVER,
HE KEPT THE CLASSICS...
OUR BURGER.
YOU CAN'T COME TO FRED'S
WITHOUT EATING THE CHEESEBURGER.
MMM!
AND ADDED SOME TWISTS
OF HIS OWN...
QUAIL AND EGGS,
OVER EASY.
THAT ARE BRINGING IN
ALL KINDS OF FANS.
MR. SHEEN,
HERE'S A STEAK.
OH, MY GOD.
NOW THAT CHIPOTLE
BROWN BUTTER'S SPICY.
MMM. VERY GOOD
AND A LITTLE SPICY.
AND ONE OF TERRY'S
HOTTEST DISHES...
TWO GREEN CHILIES COMING UP.
IS THE NEW MEXICO-STYLE
GREEN CHILI AND LAMB STEW.
IT'S SPICY STUFF.
AND YOU CAN ONLY GET IT
WHEN THE CHILIES ARE IN SEASON.
I GO TO HATCH. THAT'S A TOWN
IN SOUTHERN NEW MEXICO.
YOU GO AND BUY
YOUR CHILIES.
YES, SIR.
NO KIDDING.
WE'RE GONNA ROAST 'EM
IN THE SALAMANDER UP HERE.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
DRY ROAST THESE IN THERE FOR...
JUST WHENEVER YOU HEAR 'EM POP
AND BLISTER.
THEN I'M GONNA
FLIP 'EM OVER.
SO WHILE THAT'S DOING,
WE GET STARTED?
YES, SIR.
THIS IS MY CAST-IRON CHILI POT.
(whistles)
WE'RE GONNA RENDER
SOME BACON IN HERE.
LET THAT RENDER DOWN A MINUTE,
GET A LITTLE GREASE GOING.
WHEN I WALKED THROUGH THE DOOR
HERE, I THOUGHT I SAW
A LITTLE BIT OF A SALOON
AND NOT THE COWBOY THAT'S
PACKING UP AND GOING DOWN TO
NEW MEXICO TO BUY HATCH CHILIES.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND THROW THE ONIONS IN NOW.
LET THEM CLARIFY
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE
OF MINCED GARLIC IN THERE.
JUST FOR A SECOND
LET IT GET HOT.
WE DON'T WANT IT TO BURN.
MAKE IT BITTER.
YOU SOUND LIKE A FOOD NETWORK
CHEF THERE, BUDDY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE LAMB IN TO BROWN.
WE GOT ENOUGH RESIDUAL OIL
IN THERE NOW.
YES, SIR.
OKAY.
MY FRIENDS JUST CALL ME GUY.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
SMELLS GREAT ALREADY.
SO YOU PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON THIS LAMB.
YES, SIR.
I LOVE COOKING
WITH THE CAST-IRON.
IT HAS SO MUCH RESIDUAL HEAT,
IT STAYS RIGHT
AT THE SAME TEMPERATURE
BECAUSE OF THE THICK WALL.
SURE DOES.
NICE.
I'M GONNA SALT
AND PEPPER IT NOW.
YOU CAN'T COOK MEAT
WITHOUT SALT AND PEPPER.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT ANYBODY SAYS.
NOW I GOT A LITTLE GROUND CUMIN
I'M GONNA PUT IN.
SO IT'S GONNA HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF A SOUTHWESTERN FLAIR TO IT.
HOW THOSE CHILIES LOOKING?
THOSE ARE PERFECT.
SO NOW WE LET 'EM COOL DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
POP 'EM IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR,
PURéE 'EM.
YES, SIR. STRAIGHT INTO
THE STRAINER.
GET ALL THE SEEDS
AND THE SKINS OUT.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS GOING.
NOW WE ADD SOME WATER
IN THE POTATOES.
I LIKE TO HAVE MY POTATOES
A LITTLE BIT AL DENTE.
I DON'T LIKE 'EM MUSHY.
YOU GOT A CHUCK WAGON COOK
HERE IN TEXAS
USING THE WORD AL DENTE
TO DESCRIBE HIS POTATOES.
CRAZY.
CHUCK WAGON CRAZY.
SO IS THIS BAD BOY READY?
IT'S DONE.
SERVE ME UP, HOSS.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. I LOVE IT.
BIG FAVORITE HERE?
YES, SIR.
MMM. I LIKE THE FLAVOR.
AND THIS IS YOUR RECIPE?
YES, SIR.
IT'S MY RECIPE
RIGHT THERE.
IF YOU SAY "YES, SIR"
ONE MORE TIME,
I'LL PUT YOUR HEAD
IN THAT CHILI.
MMM. NICE JOB.
IT'S GOT A NICE BITE TO IT,
AND THE SAUCE DOESN'T MASK
THE FLAVOR OF THE LAMB.
IT WAS EXCELLENT AS USUAL.
HERE'S THOSE TWO RANCHEROS.
YOU'RE DRAGGING.
FRED'S HAS JUST ALWAYS BEEN
A SPECIAL PLACE.
AND TERRY'S PROUD
TO BE KEEPING IT THAT WAY...
YOU COOK WITH LOVE
FROM THE HEART.
30 YEARS
AS A LOCAL FAVORITE...
FRED'S TACOS.
FOR A LOCAL CROWD.
HOW LONG YOU ALL
BEEN COMING HERE?
17 YEARS.
I LIKE THAT.
HOW ABOUT YOURSELF?
ALL MY LIFE.
THIS IS A TRADITIONAL
TEXAS DINER.
WITH ALL KINDS OF CLASSICS...
CHEESEBURGERS ARE GREAT.
(man)
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK SANDWICH.
AND TERRY'S OWN TAKE ON
A TEXAS BASIC--RIB EYE STEAK.
I'VE HAD STEAKS
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
AND THIS HAS GOT THE RIGHT
SPICE, TEXAS TWANG TO IT,
PERFECTLY COOKED
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
THIS IS A LIP-ON RIB EYE.
BASICALLY THIS IS A PRIME RIB
WITHOUT THE BONE.
YES, SIR.
WE GOT THE CAP ON IT.
BUT I JUST GO AHEAD
AND RIP IT RIGHT OFF.
NOW I GO TO WORK
ON THE SILVERS.
I TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS FAT OFF HERE.
NOT TOO MUCH. WE GOT TO HAVE
SOME ON THERE FOR FLAVOR.
OKAY.
HERE AT FRED'S WE CUT
16-OUNCE RIB EYES.
LET ME SEE
THAT BAD BOY.
CHOICE?
YES, SIR. WE'RE GONNA
TURN THIS INTO A STEAK
WITH CHIPOTLE BROWN BUTTER.
LET'S GO GRILL IT.
ALL RIGHTY.
PUT A GOOD AMOUNT
OF BUTTER DOWN, SALT AND PEPPER.
LITTLE MORE ON TOP.
LITTLE MORE SALT AND PEPPER
ON THE TOP.
LITTLE GRANULATED GARLIC
AND THEN SOME ONIONS.
NOW I'M GONNA PUT
SOME CHIPOTLES ON THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF ADOBO.
ADOBO SAUCE
IN THEM CHIPOTLES.
LITTLE BIT MORE BUTTER.
DON'T SOME OF THOSE JUICES
OUT OF THAT STEAK
IS GONNA HELP COOK
THOSE ONIONS AND THE CHIPOTLE?
LEAST THAT AIN'T
GONNA BE SPICY.
GET A LITTLE JUICE COMING UP.
TIME TO FLIP.
THIS IS RIGHT
WHEN IT'S TIME TO FLIP.
CHOP THESE CHIPOTLES UP A LITTLE
BIT. I'M GONNA PLATE IT.
JUST AT THE END WHEN
YOU PULL THE STEAK OFF,
YOU DEGLAZE IT
WITH SOME BEER.
YES, SIR.
SCRAPE IT ALL UP,
THROW IT ON TOP OF THIS.
THAT'S IT.
SMELLS GREAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. GREAT SEAR
ON THE STEAK.
YOU COOKED THAT PEPPER
DOWN ENOUGH
TO WHERE
IT'S NOT JUST ALL HEAT.
THE ONIONS ARE NICE
AND SWEET.
BROTHER, ONE THING
I GOT TO TELL YA
I EXPECT TO GET OUT OF TEXAS
WAS A GREAT PIECE OF MEAT.
THAT WAS A GOOD PIECE
OF MEAT. CRAZY COOKING.
I'M A LITTLE CRAZY.
NO.
THE STEAK IS OUTSTANDING--
SOUTHWESTERN SPICE TO IT.
YOU COULD SERVE NOTHING ELSE.
I'D COME FOR THAT.
TERRY HERE AT FRED'S
ALWAYS MAKES IT RIGHT.
ONE MORE FOR TABLE SIX.
FRED'S IS JUST A CLASSIC
FORT WORTH HANGOUT.
ENJOY.
EVERYONE IS SO SWEET HERE.
THE ATMOSPHERE IS AS GENEROUS
AS THE PORTIONS.
MY FAVORITE PLACE TO EAT
IN TOWN.
SOMETHING DIFFERENT
EVERY DAY.
HE'S NOT AFRAID
TO TRY ANYTHING NEW.
BEING A COWBOY CHEF,
YOU LOVE THIS.
I LOVE THIS.
I WANT PEOPLE TO WALK AWAY
FROM FRED'S WITH A GOOD FEELING.
YOU BET.
WHOO-HOO!
(Guy) IN THEIR BELLY
OR THEIR HEAD?
BOTH.
EVERYBODY IS SOMEBODY
HERE AT FRED'S.
WE'RE SHARING THIS.
I JUST CUT IT OFF. WE AIN'T
SHARING. I'M GIVING IT TO YOU.
LET'S DO THIS.
AH!
(applause)
EVERYBODY'S A FRIEND HERE
AT FRED'S. YEAH.
UP NEXT...
FISH DIP RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE HEADING TO FLORIDA...
I'VE ACTUALLY PROBABLY HAD
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
FOR A SCIENCE LESSON...
CHECK OUR TEMPERATURE.
IN SMOKING FISH.
WHERE'S THE CHARCOAL
COME FROM?
THIS IS THE OUTDOOR
FIRE STATION.
DON'T KNOW WHAT
IT'S GONNA TASTE LIKE,
BUT I AM ON THE EDGE
OF MY SEAT.
I'M AT OLETA STATE PARK
IN NORTH MIAMI BEACH,
WHERE 70 YEARS AGO, THEY PUT UP
A SHACK TO SMOKE FISH.
NOW THE SHACK WAS TORN DOWN,
AND THE SMOKING STOPPED.
THAT'S UNTIL
A HUSBAND AND WIFE TEAM,
ALONG WITH THE HELP
OF A LOCAL FISHERMAN
THAT HAS A TRULY OFF-THE-HOOK
SMOKING STYLE,
DECIDED TO BRING THE SHACK BACK.
SO WITH ALL THAT SAID,
YOU KNOW I GOT TO CHECK OUT
THE HISTORIC BLUE MARLIN
FISH HOUSE RESTAURANT.
HERE'S YOUR SMOKED SAMPLER.
THEY'RE KNOWN FOR
THEIR SEAFOOD.
FRIED GROUPER SANDWICH.
EVERY TIME I COME HERE--
BEST FISH EVER.
EVERYTHING HERE IS FRESH.
SALMON SALAD.
SMOKED MAHI.
THE MARLIN, THAT'S FANTASTIC.
FISH DIP IS READY TO GO.
ALL THANKS TO D.J. SUAREZ...
RIGHT HERE.
AND HIS WIFE JOCELYN...
CAN I GET
THAT MARLIN SANDWICH STARTED?
WHO NEVER OWNED
A RESTAURANT BEFORE...
ENJOY, GUYS.
BUT COULDN'T SAY NO
TO THIS LOCAL LANDMARK.
YOU DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO.
I KNOW THAT I GOT
TO DO SMOKED FISH.
WE TRIED AND FAILED MISERABLY
AT FIRST.
REALLY?
YEAH. THAT'S WHEN WE GOT
IN TOUCH WITH WARREN.
LOOKING GOOD.
THAT'D BE WARREN CAMPBELL...
WE CALL HIM
THE MAD SCIENTIST.
WHO'S BEEN BRINING
AND SMOKING FISH FOR 30 YEARS.
CHECK MY TEMPERATURE.
HE EVEN CAME
WITH HIS OWN SMOKER.
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
OF SMOKERS.
MY GIZMO.
AND THAT GIZMO'S CRANKING OUT
100 POUNDS OF FISH A WEEK.
TODAY, WE'RE GONNA BE DOING
SOME MAHI MAHI.
LET'S MAKE THE BRINE.
WE'RE GONNA JUST START
WITH SOME WHITE SUGAR.
BROWN SUGAR.
THIS IS A MOLASSES-FORTIFIED
WHITE SUGAR.
IT CERTAINLY IS.
FINE BLACK PEPPER,
FINE WHITE PEPPER.
FINE POWDERED GINGER.
ONION POWDER--
TABLESPOON OF IT.
WAY TO GO BIG.
THE SAME THING
WITH GARLIC.
BACK TO THE TEASPOON.
'CAUSE THIS CAN
GET AWAY FROM YA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
CHINESE FIVE-SPICE.
SLIGHTLY BLEND THIS,
BREAK DOWN THAT BROWN SUGAR.
KOSHER SALT.
OKAY,
SO THAT'S ALL MIXED UP.
NOW WE PUT THAT
INTO THE BIG BIN.
AGUA?
HOT WATER.
IT HELPS DISSOLVE
EVERYTHING HERE.
AND IT WILL
DISSOLVE ENTIRELY
IN 100 PARTS BY WEIGHT
OF WATER.
WOW. ARE YOU LIKE A SCIENCE
TEACHER OR SOMETHING?
MAJORED IN BIOLOGY
AND CHEMISTRY.
OH, WELL, OKAY.
THE NEXT STEP,
WE USE ICE-COLD WATER.
'CAUSE YOU DON'T WANT A HOT
BRINE GOING ON YOUR FISH.
EXACTLY.
WE'RE CREATING AN OSMOSIS
WITH THE FISH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUT
ITS MOISTURE
AND FORTIFY IT
WITH OUR MOISTURE
THAT HAPPENS TO BE
A FLAVORED WATER.
YEAH.
WHOO-HOO!
(Guy) BRINE'S MADE.
SO HERE OUR MAHI.
(Warren) THIS
IS BEAUTIFUL FISH.
NOW IT GOES IN THE BRINE.
WEIGHT IT DOWN.
YOU DON'T WANT IT FLOATING
AND HAVING BRINE ON ONE PART.
EXACTLY.
OKAY, HOW LONG
WILL WE BRINE?
ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
IT GOES IN THERE.
TURN THAT ON MAX COLD.
TURN WHAT ON MAX COLD?
THE AIR CONDITIONER.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THAT IS AN AIR CONDITIONER?
5,000 B.T.U. GOES IN THERE
TO FORM THE CHEMICAL,
WHICH IS THE PROTEIN
THAT FORMS A LACQUER FINISH
TO THE FISH.
BASTE IT WITH HONEY, OIL,
SPICES AND BROWN SUGAR,
AND THEN...
WE'RE JUST GONNA DUST IT
WITH SOME COARSE PEPPER.
OKAY. BACK IN THE SMOKER?
RIGHT INTO THE SMOKER.
BUT THIS TIME
FOR A SMOKE.
OH, THIS ISN'T RIGHT.
WHERE'S THE CHARCOAL
COME FROM?
THIS IS THE OUTDOOR
FIRE STATION.
YOU'RE MAKING
YOUR OWN CHARCOAL.
BUTTONWOOD AND AVOCADO--
ALL NATIVE.
THAT'S GONNA BE YOUR BASE
FOR YOUR HEAT INSIDE?
YEAH.
AND THIS IS A DIVERTER?
YES.
WHEN IT'S INSIDE.
HEAT SHIELD.
HEAT SHIELD,
RIGHT OFF THE SPACE SHUTTLE.
SITS ON THE BRICKS.
OF COURSE, IT DOES.
HAVE WE CLOSED
OUR FLUES?
YOU JUST HAVE SOME
METALIZED DUCT TAPE
THAT YOU JUST CLOSED.
SET IN
OUR DIGITAL THERMOMETER.
LIKE A VOLTMETER,
BUT IT HAPPENS TO GIVE YOU
AN OPPORTUNITY FOR TEMPERATURE.
THEN WE TAKE
THIS KICK STICK.
I'VE SEEN PEOPLE
SPEND $50,000
ON INCREDIBLE BARBECUE UNITS.
BUT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THE CREATIVITY
AND THE INGENUITY
COME OUT OF ONE MAN.
DON'T KNOW WHAT
IT'S GONNA TASTE LIKE,
BUT I AM ON THE EDGE
OF MY SEAT.
IT SMOKES SIX HOURS.
YOU TAKE THE FIRE OUT.
THEN WE TURN ON THE A/C.
ABOUT THREE AND A HALF,
FOUR HOURS.
YOU CAN JUST SNAP THAT.
YOU SEE, THAT'S THE PELLICLE
TRYING TO HANG TOGETHER ON YOU.
THAT'S--THAT'S
THE CRAZY OLD PELLICLE.
WOW.
IT ALMOST HAS, LIKE,
A BEEF JERKY TEXTURE TO IT
ON THE OUTSIDE.
BUT ON THE INSIDE...
FLAKY.
FLAKY, CREAMY, SOFT, SMOKY.
YOU GOT TO TAKE A BITE
OF THAT.
THIS IS VERY TENDER.
MMM. I LOVE IT.
THIS IS
REALLY GOOD MAHI MAHI.
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD
SMOKY FLAVOR.
HAPPY TO SEE
THE SMOKED FISH BACK.
SURE AM.
SERVED ANY WHICH WAY.
HERE'S YOUR MAHI SANDWICH.
WHO GOT
THE BLUE MARLIN SALAD?
THAT'S ME.
EVERYTHING'S
VERY, VERY GOOD.
COME IN AND HAVE
SOMETHING NICE TO EAT,
CHECK OUT SOME SCENERY.
YOU CAN'T ASK FOR A BETTER
SETTING THAN THIS.
IT'S LIKE OLD FLORIDA.
AND SO'S THE REST
OF THE MENU
JACKED WITH FLORIDA CLASSICS
LIKE FRIED GROUPER...
IT'S FRESH, AND IT'S TENDER.
IT'S JUICY.
CONCH FRITTERS,
CRAB CAKES...
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
FISH DIP RIGHT HERE.
AND THIS
SOUTH FLORIDA SPECIALTY...
BLUE MARLIN SMOKED FISH DIP--
IT'S BEEN A REAL BIG ONE FOR US.
MMM.
THIS IS THE SMOKED MARLIN
RIGHT HERE.
WOW.
THAT IS A BIG PIECE
OF MARLIN.
WE'LL BREAK IT DOWN BY HAND.
SOAK IT IN WHOLE MILK
FOR AN HOUR.
TAKE OUT SOME OF THAT INTENSE
FISH FLAVOR THAT IT MIGHT HAVE
AND KIND OF TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SALT OUT.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOFTENED CREAM CHEESE.
WE GOT CELERY,
SOME DICED RED ONIONS,
SWEET RELISH,
GOOD TO GO, STIR THAT IN.
SO WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME FRESH LEMON.
SQUEEZE THAT IN THERE.
OKAY.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
THEN WE STIR THIS IN.
SALT, VERY LITTLE,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
HEALTHY DOSE OF THAT, PARSLEY.
ALL RIGHT,
AND THEN WE STIR THAT IN.
SEE, I LIKE THIS IDEA
THAT YOU WORK ALL THIS
INGREDIENT BASE TOGETHER.
IF YOU WERE WORKING THIS
EACH TIME AND YOU HAD THE FISH,
IT WOULD BE FISH MUSH.
OH, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA GO
AHEAD AND DRAIN THIS.
OOH, THIS LOOKS
LIKE A PLOP, PLOP.
WE'RE GONNA TRANSFER THIS
OVER TO THE BOWL.
OKAY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MIX THAT IN.
TRYING NOT TO BREAK IT
DOWN TOO MUCH.
NOT TOO MUCH.
IT NEEDS TO MARRY
FOR AT LEAST 24 HOURS.
REALLY?
THEY YOU GO, BROTHER.
GET A NICE BIG GLOB ON THERE.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. LIGHT ON THE SMOKINESS.
IT'S GOT NICE TEXTURE, TOO.
ALTHOUGH IT'S CREAMY
AND BROKEN DOWN,
IT STILL HAS GOOD BITE.
YEAH. THAT'S THE MARLIN.
THAT'S NICE.
SEE, I LIKE THAT YOU HAVE
BIG PIECES OF FISH IN THERE.
YEAH, YOU GOT TO.
THAT'S A REAL PREMIUM CUT.
NICE JOB.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S A STRAIGHT-UP STEAK.
SMOKED FISH DIP--
THE BEST BY FAR.
ISN'T IT DYNAMITE?
IT'S AWESOME.
I GOT ORDERS TO GO.
IN FACT, EVERYTHING HERE
IS GREAT.
IT'S THE BEST FISH
I'VE HAD IN A LONG TIME.
CRAB CAKE SANDWICHES.
I'VE ACTUALLY PROBABLY HAD
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
DEFINITELY OUR
NEW WATERING HOLE.
(Guy) COME HERE FOR THE NATURE.
COME HERE FOR THE SMOKED FISH.
COME HERE FOR THE GOOD TIMES.
YOU GUYS ARE AWESOME.
NICE TO MEET YA.
APPRECIATE IT, BROTHER.
OKAY, CONGRATULATIONS.
A PLEASURE, HONEY.
NEXT STOP...
GOOD HOME-COOKED COMFORT FOOD.
OREGON.
FLAKY AND DELICIOUS.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
THE BEST BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
SOUTHERN COOKING.
MMM. SOME OF THE BEST TEXTURE
IN A BISCUIT I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE'VE HIT JOINTS
THAT ARE ALL ABOUT PIZZA,
ALL ABOUT BURGERS.
WE'VE EVEN HIT A JOINT
THAT'S ALL ABOUT FRIED CARP.
AND TODAY, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE TAKE ANOTHER CULINARY LEAP
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT'S ALL
ABOUT THE TENDER, FLAKY--
IS THE ANTICIPATION KILLING YOU
OR WHAT?--
THE TENDER, FLAKY, GRAVY-TOPPED
SOUTHERN DELICACY
KNOWN AS BISCUITS.
WELCOME TO PORTLAND'S
PINE STATE BISCUITS.
FULL TRAY COMING OUT.
THE BEST BISCUIT EVER.
(man) ABOUT THREE MINUTES
ON BISCUITS.
THIS IS THE PERFECT BITE.
MMM.
BISCUIT
AND HUCKLEBERRY JAM.
A BISCUIT
WITH SAUSAGE GRAVY.
DO YOU RUN HERE?
SOME GOOD HOME-COOKED
COMFORT FOOD.
I GOT SOME GRAVY COMING.
ALL SERVED UP
BY COLLEGE BUDDIES
BRIAN SNYDER, WALT ALEXANDER
AND KEVIN ASHLEY...
HOT TRAY.
WE'RE ALL FROM
NORTH CAROLINA.
ALL OF YOU?
HOW Y'ALL DOING?
WHO ENDED UP
IN PORTLAND,
RECONNECTED
AND OPENED THIS PLACE.
WHY BISCUITS?
'CAUSE WE MISSED 'EM.
PEOPLE NEEDED A PLACE
THEY COULD STOP BY
AND GET A GOOD,
HEARTY BREAKFAST.
LIKE THIS
NORTH CAROLINA CLASSIC...
THE BEST BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
SO GET ME STARTED.
FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE?
UNBLEACHED.
BAKING POWDER. BAKING SODA.
WHY THE TWO?
IT'S JUST WHAT GIVES US
THE BEST RISE, FLAKINESS.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
AND WE WHISK THIS TOGETHER.
PUT THE DRY INGREDIENTS
TOGETHER FIRST.
THEN WE GOT THE WET MIX.
BUTTERMILK.
IS THAT BUTTERMILK LIGHT?
REDUCED FAT.
OH.
WE GOT SOME FULL-FAT YOGURT,
SOME EGGS.
WE'LL WHISK THIS ALL TOGETHER,
AND THEN WE SHRED THE BUTTER.
WHOA, WE'RE GONNA WHAT?
OH, THIS IS AWESOME.
DUDE, I HAVE SEEN BISCUITS
ALL OVER THE WORLD,
I'VE NEVER SEEN
BUTTER SHREDDING.
IT'S ROCK-HARD FROZEN.
EXACTLY.
IT'S GONNA CREATE
FLAKE DELICIOUSNESS.
YOU GOT IT.
CHECK THAT OUT.
THAT'S NUTS.
YEAH.
ACTUALLY, IT'S BUTTER.
SO NOW WE GOT
TO ACT FAST,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT THAT
BUTTER TO MELT, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO WE GET IT INCORPORATED.
SO IT DOESN'T SEPARATE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL YOU DO
IS ADD THAT LIQUID
AND GIVE IT, LIKE, TWO
OR THREE SPINS, AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
FLOUR THE BOARD.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE BRINGING OUT
THE DOUGH.
YOU JUST INCORPORATE IT ENOUGH
TO GET IT OUT OF THE BOWL,
BUT YOU STILL GOT
SOME WORK TO DO, CORRECT?
EXACTLY.
THEY ARE HANDBUILT.
THEY'RE READY TO ROLL.
SO WE'LL ROLL THIS OUT,
AND WE'LL DO SOME FOLDING.
NOT ONLY DO YOU HAVE THE FLOUR
CREATING ALL OF THIS LAYER,
YOU'RE CREATING LAYER AS YOU
FOLD THEM TOP OF EACH OTHER.
EXACTLY.
SO WE'RE READY TO CUT.
EXACT RIGHT SIZE.
GOES IN THE OVEN.
JUST BELOW 400,
12 TO 15 MINUTES.
HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE BUTTER.
ABOUT TWO TO THREE MINUTES
BEFORE WE PULL 'EM OUT.
I'M GONNA TRY TO PICK OUT
THE ONE I THINK IS BEST.
THAT ONE. WELL, NOW
YOU'VE DONE BROKE IT.
WELL, LET'S COVER IT
WITH GRAVY.
OLIVE OIL, PURéED ONIONS,
GROUND PORK, WATER.
GIVE THAT A STIR.
AND SOME FLOUR.
SAUSAGE SPICE MIX--
CAYENNE, SALT,
PEPPER, NUTMEG,
CORIANDER, THYME
AND SAGE.
HEAVY CREAM,
WHOLE MILK.
MAKE A BUTTER
AND FLOUR ROUX.
ADD THE ROUX.
MAPLE SYRUP.
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT.
LITTLE CHIVES.
LITTLE PAPRIKA
FOR SOME COLOR.
I DIG IT. OKAY.
MMM.
THAT IS SOME OF THE BEST TEXTURE
IN A BISCUIT I'VE EVER HAD.
HAS THE FLAKINESS,
AND IT'S LIGHT,
BUT THERE'S REAL SUBSTANCE
TO IT.
BUT, THEN AGAIN, I COULD BE
EATING A PAPER TOWEL
WITH THAT GRAVY ON IT.
WOW. MMM. KILLER.
I'D SAY THESE ARE SOME OF
THE BEST BISCUITS I'VE EVER HAD.
FLAKY AND DELICIOUS.
BISCUITS COMING.
THE BISCUIT THAT CAN HANDLE
WHATEVER YOU WANT TO
PUT IN THIS BISCUIT.
YEAH, WHATEVER,
LIKE STEWED APPLES.
YOU GOT TO HAVE A SIDE
OF HUCKLEBERRY JAM,
KIND OF AN OREGON DEAL.
SHIITAKE MUSHROOM GRAVY.
MY FAVORITE'S
THE "DOUBLE DOWN" MONEY BALL.
(woman) TWO BISCUITS,
GRAVY ALL OVER THE PLACE
AND THEN AN EGG ON TOP.
BISCUITS GOING IN.
IT'S A BISCUIT PLACE,
BUT THE FRIED CHICKEN
IS THE BEST IN TOWN.
SO YOU KNOW WHERE
THIS IS GOING.
THIS GIANT SANDWICH.
THE REGGIE?
RIGHT.
YOU SEE, BRIAN WANTED
TO NAME HIS SON REGGIE,
AND HIS WIFE SAID NO WAY.
SO HE FIGURED, HEY, THE NEXT
BEST THING WAS A SANDWICH.
FIRST THINGS FIRST, WE'RE GONNA
MAKE SOME FRIED CHICKEN.
WE'LL MAKE UP THE MARINADE
OR THE SOAK.
A LITTLE MORE
OF THAT BUTTERMILK.
LITTLE CAYENNE.
AND WE'LL WHISK THAT UP.
THEN WE'LL SLICE UP
THE CHICKEN.
WHOA. THIN FRIED CHICKEN.
BISCUIT PORTIONS.
SOAK THIS FOR 24 HOURS.
OKAY.
MAKE UP THE DREDGE.
SOME MORE OF THAT
BISCUIT FLOUR.
THIS IS ACTUALLY SELF-RISING.
COARSE GROUND PEPPER.
SO WE'LL WHISK THIS UP.
THEN WE GOT THE EGG WASH.
LITTLE HOT SAUCE?
YEP.
WOW. DARE YOU TO LICK IT.
NO, THANKS.
SO THEN WE'LL SEASON
THE CHICKEN.
MORE SEASONING.
GARLIC SALT, SALT, PEPPER
AND CAJUN SEASONING.
WHOA.
WE'LL DIP IT.
AND THEN THE FLOUR
ON TOP OF THAT,
BECAUSE YOU HAVE A TENDENCY
WITH SOME OF THOSE SPICES,
THEY CAN BURN, SO THE CLOSER
THEY ARE DOWN TO THE BIRD,
BETTER OFF YOU ARE.
YOU GOT IT.
HE KNOWS WHAT'S GOING ON.
AND WE'LL FRY IT UP.
LOOK AT THESE. THAT IS SOME
GOOD-LOOKING FRIED CHICKEN.
YOU JUST SHOWED
YOUR NORTH CAROLINA PASSPORT
JUST NOW.
WE'LL GET A BISCUIT.
FRIED CHICKEN, BACON, GRAVY
AND CHEDDAR.
HOW DO YOU GET AROUND
ON THAT ONE?
DON'T BE SHY.
AIN'T THAT KIND OF GUY.
YOU KNOW THE HUNCH?
YEP, I KNOW THE HUNCH.
MMM.
OH, YOU DO.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
EVERYBODY COMES TOGETHER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MMM.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING ON IT.
I HAD MY REGGIE AND THEN
MOST OF MY WIFE'S REGGIE.
(man) THIS PLACE
IS GREAT.
IT'S NOT JUST BACON
AND EGGS AND HASH BROWNS.
IT'S SOMETHING
REALLY UNIQUE.
LIKE THEIR TAKE ON
THE OLD CLUB SANDWICH.
TWO CLUBS DOWN.
BUT INSTEAD OF BREAD,
THEY'RE USING FRIED GRITS.
GREAT COMBINATION OF TASTE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
I'M A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL.
HOW YOU DOING ON BISCUITS, WALT?
THE BOYS AT PINE STATE BISCUITS
ARE BRINGING PORTLAND
THE SOUTHERN-STYLE FOOD
THEY GREW UP WITH
IN NORTH CAROLINA.
WHAT THEY'RE DOING
IS REALLY AUTHENTIC.
LIKE FRIED CHICKEN,
BISCUITS STUFFED
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING
AND GET A LOAD OF THIS.
PINE STATE FRIED CLUB.
BUT THIS CLUB'S
NOT SERVED UP ON BREAD.
NO, NOT EVEN A BISCUIT.
HOW ABOUT SOME
DEEP-FRIED GRIT CAKES?
YOU GUYS USE REAL GRITS?
WE USE REAL GRITS.
GOOD WAY TO START OFF
THIS CONVERSATION.
YEAH.
I'M A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL.
SO FIRST WE POUR THE LIQUID IN,
WHICH IS DAIRY AND WATER,
AND WE'LL BRING THAT
TO A BOIL.
WE'LL WHISK IN THE GRITS.
LET IT SET UP WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
AND THEN WE'LL SEASON IT
WITH PEPPER AND SALT.
POUR IT IN A PAN--
SMALL BATCH, ARTISAN GRITS.
AND WHERE ARE THEY?
CAN I SEE WHERE THEY'RE COMING?
GET THOSE IN THE CAR.
MAKE A LOAF OUT OF IT.
WE START BY MAKING
A COUPLE LITTLE GRIT CAKES,
AND WE'LL FLOUR THESE UP.
OKAY, SO WHAT
DO WE GOT HERE?
GOT SOME
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
YEP. WE PRE-PREPPED
THE FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
THE CHICKEN.
THAT'S THE CHICKEN.
WE'LL PUT THE FRIED GREEN TOMATO
AND THE CHICKEN IN ONE BASKET.
PUT THE GRIT CAKES
IN THE OTHER.
THOSE WILL TAKE THREE,
FOUR MINUTES TO FRY.
WE TAKE THE JOHNSTON COUNTY
COUNTRY HAM, SLICED THIN.
THIS IS SOUTHERN PROSCIUTTO.
YOU GOT IT.
WHITE SHARP CHEDDAR.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT ON THAT
AND MELT THAT CHEESE.
THAT'S A TOPPING ALSO?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHILE THAT'S HAPPENING,
WE'RE MAKING PIMENTO CHEESE.
IS THAT GOAT CHEESE?
YEAH.
IN PIMENTO CHEESE?
THIS IS NOT YOUR TYPICAL
SHARP CHEDDAR PIMENTO
MAYONNAISE VERSION.
THE PIMENTOS--
THOSE WERE JARRED.
SEASON IT UP,
SALT AND PEPPER TO TASTE.
AND ROASTED GARLIC.
WOW.
SESAME OIL AND THYME.
AND THEN THIS IS BUTTER.
YOU'RE FREAKING ME OUT.
NEXT, SHARP WHITE CHEDDAR.
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT.
THAT'S THE MOST UNIQUE
PIMENTO CHEESE I'VE EVER TRIED.
IT'S GOOD, THOUGH.
I THINK WE'RE GOOD. PLATE 'EM
UP, AND WE'LL TOP 'EM.
JOHNSTON COUNTY COUNTRY HAM,
FRIED CHICKEN.
ON TOP OF FRIED GRITS.
PIMENTO CHEESE
AND THE FRIED GREEN TOMATO.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW I GOT TO DRESS
THE CHICKEN.
HONEY AND GREEN TABASCO.
AND THAT'S THE PINE STATE
FRIED CLUB.
LET'S GET IN
THE TOMATO FIRST.
GOOD. PIMENTO WORKS
EXACTLY WHERE IT SHOULD.
SINCE I'M A HAM JUNKIE,
I THINK THIS
IS A NEAT LITTLE IDEA HERE,
THE HAM
WRAPPED AROUND THE CHEESE.
MM-HMM. OH.
OKAY, FRIED CHICKEN.
THE CHICKEN'S THE BEST.
THE SWEET OF THE HONEY,
THE HOT SAUCE, THE GREEN TABASCO
WITH THE CRUNCHY CHICKEN
AND THIS CREAMY GRITS
WITH A LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM--
AS MUCH AS I WANTED THAT HAM
TO BE THE WINNER-WINNER,
THAT RIGHT THERE
IS THE CHICKEN DINNER.
THAT'S A GREAT TRIO.
(Guy) HOW ARE YOU ENJOYING
YOUR FRIED GREEN TOMATOES
WITH THE PIMENTO?
THAT IS PROBABLY THE BEST.
GREAT COMBINATION OF TASTE.
TWO MORE GOING DOWN.
SIMPLE AND DELICIOUS.
BEST BISCUITS IN PORTLAND,
I'VE FOUND.
WE'LL COME BACK, FOR SURE.
GUYS, CONGRATULATIONS.
APPRECIATE IT.
DYNAMITE PLACE.
KILLER BISCUITS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE "D"--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I WANT A LITTLE
AUCTIONEER TRAINING.
HERE $35, $45, $55, NOW $65.
I'M $125 NOW, $150.
HEY, GONNA HAVE IT NOW,
GONNA HAVE HALF,
GONNA HAVE IT ALL,
GONNA HAVE IT ALL NOW.