LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
OKAY, THIS TRIP!
YOU'RE REALLY GONNA PUT
A GOAT HEAD IN THERE?
YEAH.
WHO'D A THUNK IT, IN BOISE,
A 52-YEAR OLD CLASSIC.
WHERE ELSE DO YOU HAVE A CHEF
IN A DRIVE-IN?
YOU'RE A LEGEND.
WHERE THIS IS
DRIVE-IN COOKING.
IT'S A PRETTY
UNIQUE EXPERIENCE.
THIS IS A PRIME RIB.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE KICKER
IS ON THIS?
WHAT?
THAT AU JUS.
IN ARLINGTON, TEXAS.
FRESH FRIED CHICKEN.
A JOINT TURNING TEXANS ON.
THIS PLACE IS FANTASTIC.
TO JAMAICAN FAVORITES.
IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
THE CURRY GOAT
IS MY FAVORITE.
PURE JAMAICAN FOOD.
DELICIOUS.
AND IN SANTA FE,
WHERE THEY'RE MAKING SUBS
OUT OF PIZZA DOUGH.
AND PUTTING GREEN CHILE
ON THE PIES.
GREEN CHILE IS WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT.
I'VE GOTTA HAVE MORE PIZZAS
WITH GREEN CHILES ON IT.
THAT ROCKS!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON,
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
I'M HERE IN BOISE, IDAHO,
AND I'VE GOT A POP QUIZ FOR YOU.
WHEN I SAY DRIVE-IN
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
WELL, YOU'RE THINKING FRIES,
YOU'RE THINKING MILKSHAKES
AND KILLER BURGERS.
BUT ARE YOU THINKING CHEF,
I MEAN, A REAL CHEF?
AN ACS CERTIFIED CHEF, AMERICAN
CULINARY FEDERATION CHEF,
THAT'S FRESH CUTTING FISH
AND DOING PRIME RIB?
WELCOME TO
THE WESTSIDE DRIVE-IN.
NUMBER 67 AND 34.
PRIME RIB
AND THE BAKED POTATO.
SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALLS,
DELICIOUS.
I'LL HAVE
THE POMODORO FETTUCCINI.
WE NEED MORE POMODORO.
IT'S NOT A NORMAL
KIND OF DRIVE-THRU.
ORDER UP.
AND NOT A NORMAL KIND OF
DRIVE-THRU COOK.
ROASTED PEPPER
KETCHUP PLEASE.
YOU'RE A LEGEND,
CHEF LOU.
WHERE ELSE DO YOU HAVE
A CHEF IN A DRIVE-IN?
IT TOOK PROBABLY
THREE OR FOUR MONTHS BEFORE
PEOPLE FIGURED OUT
THAT I WAS A CHEF
THAT OWNED A DRIVE-IN.
A '50s LANDMARK FROM
LOU AARON'S CHILDHOOD.
I GREW UP ABOUT
SIX BLOCKS WEST.
CAME DOWN HERE
ALL THE TIME FOR SHAKES.
AND AFTER 27 YEARS
AS A CHEF,
HE JUMPED AT THE CHANCE
TO BUY THIS JOINT.
I BROUGHT REAL COOKS IN,
CHANGED THE MENU.
WHAT WAS ONE OF THE FIRST
CHANGES YOU MADE TO THE MENU?
WELL, I PUT PRIME RIB
ON IT.
I'D END UP GOING TO
A NICE RESTAURANT
PAYING 35, 40 BUCKS.
SO I DECIDED I'M PUTTING
PRIME RIB ON FOR LOU.
NOW IT'S A FRIDAY
AND SATURDAY SPECIAL...
PRIME BAKER ON FOUR.
FOLKS ARE PULLING IN FOR.
THIS IS A PRIME RIB.
IT'S SOME OF THE BEST
PRIME RIB YOU'LL EVER FIND.
HERE'S OUR RUB.
ALL OF THIS?
SO THE CAST OF CHARACTERS
ARE SALT...
GRANULATED GARLIC.
SUGAR.
WHITE PEPPER.
BLACK PEPPER, WHOLE THYME,
ONION POWDER, DILL WEED,
PAPRIKA, CHILI POWDER,
CUMIN.
CELERY SALT
AND POULTRY SEASONING.
IS IT CREAM OF TARTAR?
NO, IT'S CORNSTARCH.
THEN YOU JUST
MIX IT TOGETHER.
SO NICE PIECE
OF PRIME RIB THERE.
SO WE'RE GONNA RUB IT ON
ALL OVER.
THERE WE GO.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GARLIC GONE WILD.
NEXT, FLOUR, I LIKE TO COOK
ALL MY ROASTS WITH FLOUR,
BECAUSE IT SEALS IN
THE MOISTURE.
OH, THIS IS INTERESTING.
WE SAVE EVERYTHING,
ONION PEEL, CELERY,
CARROTS.
THIS IS ACTUALLY WHAT
WE'RE GOING TO ROAST IT ON.
I LIKE IT, YOU EITHER HAVE
A RACK OR SOME KIND OF BED.
AND I GOTTA DO
ONE MORE THING.
OKAY.
WHAT IN THE WORLD.
BACON GREASE.
OH, THAT'S RIDICULOUS,
I'M GONNA HUG YOU.
THEN THE LAST INGREDIENT
IS ROSEMARY.
WHICH IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE ON
PRIME RIB.
WHAT KIND OF TIME,
WHAT KIND OF TEMP?
SO 425,
I GO 20 MINUTES.
DROP IT DOWN, FINISH UP
TWO HOURS AT 275.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR AU JUS.
WE START OFF WITH A BEEF STOCK,
BACON GREASE AGAIN, BEEF BONES.
AND I'M JUST GONNA
SEAR THESE BONES.
SO YOU'RE DOING REAL
OLD-SCHOOL BEEF STOCK.
WE MAKE CHICKEN STOCK,
TURKEY STOCK, SHRIMP STOCK.
WOW, DO YOU REALLY THINK
YOU GET FLAVOR OUT OF
THE ONION SKIN?
EVERY LITTLE BIT HELPS.
OH, I AGREE.
BASIC HERBS, THYME,
ROSEMARY.
THEN SOMETHING YOU EXPECT
TO FIND IN EVERY DRIVE-IN,
JUNIPER BERRIES.
THIS ADDS A NICE,
MELLOW FLAVOR TO THE STOCK.
BAY LEAVES, EVERYBODY'S
IN THE POOL.
I WANT TO DE-GLAZE THE PAN,
NICE COLD WATER.
COLD WATER SHOCKS IT
AND BRINGS IT OUT.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA TRANSFER THIS
TO BIG STOCK POT,
FILL UP WITH WATER,
YOU LET IT GO FOR EIGHT HOURS,
AND YOU MAKE YOURSELF
SOME RIGHTEOUS STOCK
AT A DRIVE-THRU.
THAT'S A GOOD LOOKING
RIB, MAN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
ALL OF THAT INTO AN AU JUS.
SO WE'RE READY TO GO NOW.
THAT IS A GREAT LOOKING
AU JUS.
WE CUT 8-OUNCE PORTIONS.
THAT IS MEDIUM-RARE
TO MEDIUM.
SERVE IT UP WITH
SOME HORSERADISH.
LOOK AT THE CRUST
THAT BUILDS UP RIGHT THERE.
PEOPLE LOVE THAT.
WOW, THAT CRUST REALLY
HAS SOME FLAVOR, HUH?
YEAH, GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT
RIGHT THERE,
LOOK AT THAT AU JUS.
IT'S AS GOOD AS
ANY PRIME RIB YOU'LL FIND.
IT'S TENDER,
IT'S DONE THE RIGHT WAY.
KNOW WHAT THE KICKER IT
ON THIS?
WHAT?
THAT AU JUS.
OH.
PRIME RIB WISE,
HOW'S HE DOING?
OH, EXCELLENT.
IT'S A PRETTY UNIQUE
EXPERIENCE TO COME TO A PLACE
WHERE YOU'D NORMALLY THINK YOU'D
JUST GET BURGERS AND FRIES.
BUT LOU'S DOING THOSE, TOO...
TWO DADDY-O'S
COMING UP.
HIS WAY.
CAN I GET A DADDY-O,
PLEASE.
TWO BURGER PATTIES,
HAM, BACON,
TWO TYPES OF CHEESE.
SO HALF A COW,
AND A QUARTER PIG?
IT'S RESTAURANT QUALITY FOOD...
TWO CHICKEN FETT SPECIALS UP.
IN A DRIVE-THRU.
JUST WHAT YOU'D EXPECT TO SEE
AT A DRIVE-IN.
WOW, THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THE MEATLOAF IS JUST TO DIE FOR.
THAT'S A BIG MEATLOAF
SANDWICH.
THIS IS SERIOUS FOOD.
THAT'S PULLING IN
A SERIOUS CROWD.
PESTO CHICKEN FETT
UP ON FOUR.
3,800 HUNDRED ORDERS A WEEK.
WHATEVER THEY'RE EATING,
CAJUN CHICKEN REUBEN.
FROM PASTA BY THE BUCKETFUL,
A LITTLE PESTO...
TO THE MONTE CRISTO.
WELL...
AND THIS LOCAL CLASSIC.
FINGER STEAK.
MUST BE AN IDAHO THING.
I WOULD SAY THAT 80 PERCENT
OF THE RESTAURANTS IN BOISE
HAVE THESE ON THE MENU.
NO.
THIS IS JUST BOTTOM SIRLOIN
CUT INTO STRIPS.
DIP IN SOME FLOUR, YOU WANT
TO KEEP THEM ALL SEPARATE.
IT'S FINGER STEAK.
FINGER STEAK.
THROW IT IN OUR BATTER.
HEAVY ON THE GARLIC
AND BLACK PEPPER.
NO, NO IT'S LOOKS GOOD
ON YOU, JUDGE.
HOLD THEM UP A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE THEY GO DOWN INTO IT.
THEY DON'T TAKE LONG
TO COOK.
GET THE LAST ONE IN THERE,
WE'RE ALMOST DONE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
LET THEM DRAIN
JUST A SECOND.
AND WHAT ARE WE
SERVING THEM WITH?
COCKTAIL SAUCE.
SPICY COCKTAIL SAUCE.
JUST HORSERADISH
AND LEMON JUICE,
ADD CHILE SAUCE.
TENDER LITTLE FINGERS
OF STEAK.
THIS IS A FIRST.
NICE AND CRUNCHY,
YOU GET A LOT OF MEAT FLAVOR.
IT'S TENDER.
AND THE COCKTAIL SAUCE
ODDLY ENOUGH...
A MATCH MADE IN HEAVEN.
THAT'S A WHOLE ORDER,
WHO COULD EAT ALL THAT?
YOU'RE GONNA EAT THEM ALL.
CONVERTIBLE CAMARO,
NOT A DUMP TRUCK.
EXCELLENT, THE STEAK
IS WELL COOKED.
THE COCKTAIL SAUCE
FINISHES IT OFF NICELY.
THE QUALITY OF THE FOOD,
IT'S GREAT.
PRIME RIB UP ON FOUR.
GREAT MEAL ON A HIGH SCHOOL
CAFETERIA TRAY.
THERE YOU GO.
GREAT GOURMET FOOD
AT A DRIVE-THRU,
WHAT ELSE CAN YOU ASK FOR?
THERE'S YOUR FORTUNE'S
FOR TODAY.
AND THE FORTUNE COOKIES
ARE REALLY COOL.
WHOA.
YEAH, I WAS HERE LAST WEEK
AND IT SAID,
"YOU WILL MEET A FAMOUS
COOKING SHOW HOST."
WITH SPIKED HAIR.
THIS IS DEFINITELY A GEM,
YOU'RE BLOWING IT UP.
WELL, IT WORKS.
NICE TO MET YOU CHEF.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO ARLINGTON, TEXAS.
THE FOOD IS JUST
EXCEPTIONAL.
CURRIED GOAT.
JAMAICAN COOKING.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE CURRY,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE HABANERO,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I ALWAYS DIG ROLLING
THROUGH TEXAS.
I MEAN, WE'VE HAD
SOME GREAT SUCCESS
FINDING SOME UNIQUE JOINTS.
BUT I GOTTA ADMIT,
AFTER A WHILE
WE KIND OF THINK
WE'VE SEEN IT ALL.
UNTIL I ROLLED THROUGH
ARLINGTON, TEXAS,
AND FIND THE KIND OF FOOD
WE HAVEN'T SEEN MUCH
OF ANYWHERE,
JAMAICAN FOOD.
SO IT'S TIME
TO LOCK THEM UP
AND HEAD INTO
JAMAICA GATES.
THIS IS AUTHENTIC,
PURE JAMAICAN FOOD.
THE JERK PORK,
LOOK AT THAT.
IT TAKES LIKE IT'S FROM
BOSTON BEACH IN JAMAICA.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
ONE CABBAGE AND PINEAPPLE
SALAD.
OXTAIL.
THAT'S SOMETHING YOU DON'T
GET A LOT OF PLACES.
IF YOU WANT REAL
JAMAICA FOOD,
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME.
FOR THE HOME COOKING
BARBARA RENFRO GREW UP WITH
IN JAMAICA.
I'VE GOT A CURRIED CHICKEN
GOING.
AND KEPT TURNING OUT
FOR FAMILY AND FRIENDS WHEN
SHE MOVED TO TEXAS.
PUT RICE AND PEAS ON THAT.
PEOPLE STARTED REALLY
PUSHING ME, YOUR FOOD IS GOOD.
AND NOW, SHE'S GOT ONE.
WHY DON'T YOU GET
A RESTAURANT.
AND A GROWING FAN CLUB, TOO.
FRESH IN THE WINDOW.
CURRY GOAT.
THE REASON WHY I COME HERE
IS IT'S REALLY AUTHENTIC.
AND ALL HOMEMADE,
LIKE THE RED STRIPE CHICKEN.
ROASTED RED SNAPPER.
IT'S RED STRIPE BEER
AND COCONUT MILK.
IT'S GREAT,
IT'S REALLY FLAVORFUL.
AND WHAT BARBARA CALLS
THE JAMAICAN NATIONAL DISH.
CURRIED GOAT IS
MY FAVORITE.
GOAT IS WHAT WE USE
AT EVERY FUNCTION.
WEDDINGS,
EVERY KIND OF CELEBRATION.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
GET BUSY ON IT,
OKAY, HEY-HO.
IT'S NOT SCARY,
IT'S JUST THE NOISE.
OKAY, SO NOW THAT
WE'VE GOT OUR GOAT
CHOPPED UP,
WHAT'S THE GIDDY UP HERE?
PEPPER, HABONEROS,
THYME, SOME ONIONS, GARLIC,
JAMAICAN SEASONING,
A COMBINATION OF GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, SALT,
A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN.
AND THEN A COUPLE OF
YOUR SECRET SPICES.
A COUPLE OF MY
SECRET SPICES.
YOU'LL TELL ME OFF
CAMERA RIGHT?
I'M NOT GONNA LET
EVERYBODY KNOW.
AND THEN CURRY POWDER,
I MIGHT NEED A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER IN THERE.
OKAY, IS THAT GOOD?
SOMETIMES I DO A LITTLE TASTE,
MAN, YOU'VE BEEN IN THE KITCHEN.
I DON'T TASTE RAW GOAT,
MMM-MM, NIBBLE ON THAT.
SO WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
WE MARINATE THIS
OVERNIGHT.
SO LET'S MARINATE IT
AND COOK IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
AND PUT IT IN THE POT.
WHAT DO YOU CALL GOAT
IN JAMAICAN.
GOAT.
OKAY, LITTLE MORE WATER
AND THEN WE'RE GOING
TO LET IT SIMMER.
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
REALLY?
IT DEPENDS ON
HOW OLD THE GOAT IS.
THIS IS PRETTY YOUNG,
THE MEAT IS VERY TENDER.
THE GOAT IS READY.
LOOK AT THE COLOR
ON THAT.
WITH WHITE RICE
AND UNCOOKED CABBAGE
AND CARROTS.
OH MY GOSH, THERE'S
A LITTLE HEAT IN THE BACK.
A LITTLE BIT OF
HABANERO COMING THROUGH,
AND TENDER.
THAT'S THE BITE RIGHT THERE.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS OF THE CURRY,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE HABANERO,
THE TEXTURE OF THE RICE
AND THE BITTERNESS
OF THE CABBAGE.
CAN'T SAY I EAT
A LOT OF GOAT,
BUT THAT'S GO-TO GOAT,
DELICIOUS.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
RIGHT COMBINATION
OF SPICES AND SEASON,
CLASSIC CURRY GOAT.
CLASSIC.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS
DELICIOUS.
IT'S JUST LIKE MY GRANDMOTHER
COOKING IN HER KITCHEN.
WE WANT YOU TO FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE IN JAMAICA.
SAUTEED VEGETABLES
AND CABBAGE.
IF WE HAD A COUPLE
OF PALM TREES.
THE SAME PRESENTATION
YOU GET AT HOME.
WITH ALL THE SAME SIDES.
CABBAGE AND MIXED VEGETABLES.
WHITE RICE WITH PLANTAINS,
RICE AND PEAS.
ARE THEY RICE AND PEAS,
OR RICE-N-PEAS?
RICE COOKED WITH
RED BEANS.
ALL OF THEM IS PEAS
FOR US.
YOU STOPPED THE CONFUSION.
JAMAICAN FOOD IS SOMETHING
THAT YOU'RE NOT USED
TO SEEING.
THE SEASONINGS, THE SPICES,
REALLY ARE AUTHENTIC.
OH YEAH, IT'S AUTHENTIC...
GOAT HEAD SOUP.
YOU REALLY PUT
A GOAT HEAD IN THERE?
YEAH.
AND THAT'S NOT ALL,
THE GOAT FEET, THE STOMACH,
CARROTS, SOME DUMPLINGS.
WHAT'S THE NOODLE RIGHT THERE?
OH, THAT'S NOT A NOODLE.
THAT'S NOT A NOODLE.
OKAY.
VERY GOATY,
WHAT'S THAT PART?
IT'S CALLED THE TRIPE.
SEE HOW TENDER IT IS.
IT IS TENDER.
ONCE YOU GET OVER
THE IDEA,
IT'S VERY FLAVORFUL.
I HAVEN'T HAD GREAT
GOAT SOUP SINCE
I LEFT JAMAICA.
HAPPY?
I'M HAPPY.
LIKE BROWN STEWED FISH.
THIS IS PURE JAMAICAN FOOD,
AND BARBARA'S THROWING
THE WHOLE FISH INTO THE POT
FOR THIS HEAVY HITTER.
IT'S GREAT,
IT'S REALLY FLAVORFUL.
A REALLY AUTHENTIC TASTE.
BROWN STEWED FISH,
WHAT DO WE GOT?
A RED SNAPPER.
GONNA PUT SOME
LITTLE SLICE IN IT.
THIS IS A MIXTURE OF
BLACK PEPPER, GARLIC,
ONION, RED PEPPER, CILANTRO,
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
DO WE PUT SOME IN
THE CAVITY?
YES, THAT'S READY
TO BE FRIED.
WE'RE GONNA FRY HIM.
BUT BEFORE WE DO THAT, WE'RE
GONNA MAKE OUR BROWN SAUCE?
BROWN STEW FISH SAUCE,
PUT SOME WATER IN THE POT.
OIL, A LITTLE ONION,
HABANERO PEPPER, TOMATOES.
NOW, DO YOU MAKE THE STEW
EVERY DAY, OR DO YOU
MAKE IT AHEAD OF TIME?
YEAH, WE MAKE IT FRESH
EVERY DAY.
THYME, ALLSPICE,
SEASON SALT.
YES.
THIS IS A FISH SAUCE.
CAN I TRY IT?
TASTES A LITTLE BIT
LIKE A STEAK SAUCE,
IT'S GOOD THOUGH.
POUR ALL OF THAT
IN HERE.
THEN WE'LL FRY THE FISH
AND BRING IT OVER?
YES.
I LIKE IT.
DROP IT IN THE HOT OIL.
MIGHT TAKE ABOUT
TWO TO THREE MINUTES.
SO NOW HE GOES INTO
THE HOT TUB OF FLAVOR.
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
SMELLS AWESOME.
WOW, LOOK STAYS TOGETHER,
NICE DISMOUNT.
NOW WE POUR
THE SAUCE ON IT.
SHOULD I START AT
THE KNEE,
OR MOVE RIGHT ON IN
TO THE TENDERLOIN
OF THIS GUY?
YOUR CHOICE.
LOOK AT THAT.
REALLY NICE TEXTURE,
NICE FLAVOR.
NOT TOO SPICY?
NOT AT ALL.
THAT'S GREAT,
DO I GET TO KEEP THE HEAD?
YEAH.
AND EAT IT?
I LOVE MY FISH HEAD,
EVERY LAST BIT OF IT.
THEN YOU AND I ARE
THE PERFECT DATE.
GOOD.
THAT HAS BIG FLAVOR,
EXCELLENT FLAVOR.
NICE, LIGHT,
ALWAYS PERFECT.
THE FOOD IS JUST EXCEPTIONAL.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
THE CURRIED GOAT.
I CAN COME TO A RESTAURANT
AND JUST FEEL AT HOME.
SO THESE FOLKS ARE
DOING IT THE RIGHT WAY?
JUST TRYING TO MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING IS DONE THE WAY
I WANTED IT DONE.
I'M JAMAICAN AND THIS IS
THE ONLY PLACE I'D RECOMMEND
FOR JAMAICAN FOOD.
EVERYBODY THAT COMES IN
LOOKS REALLY HAPPY.
WE DO TRY TO MAKE
THEM HAPPY.
I THINK YOU DO.
NEXT STOP, NEW MEXICO.
IT'S UNIQUE, SPECIAL,
IT'S THE BEST.
WHERE THEY'RE DOING PIZZA...
CORNMEAL GIVES IT
A REALLY SWEET CRUNCHY FLAVOR.
THEIR WAY.
I REALLY LIKE THIS CRUST.
AS I CRUISE THROUGH
THE COUNTRY ON TRIPLE D,
I FIND OUT THAT EVERY TOWN,
BIG OR SMALL,
USUALLY HAS A DINER
THAT YOU'VE JUST GOTTA HIT,
A BARBECUE JOINT THAT'S GOT
A LINE OUT THE DOOR,
OR A PIZZA PLACE THAT
EVERYBODY DIGS.
TODAY, I'M IN
SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO,
AND I HEAR YOU'VE GOTTA
CHECK OUT BACKROAD PIZZA.
WONDERFUL PIZZA.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S UNIQUE, IT'S SPECIAL,
NO COMPARISON.
THE PIZZA'S ALWAYS GOOD.
ONE SLICE CHEESE IN.
CLASSIC.
IT'S VERY DELICIOUS.
OR LOADED UP WITH GREEN CHILES,
NEW MEXICO STYLE.
THE GREEN CHILE IS WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT.
I'VE GOTTA HAVE MORE PIZZA
WITH GREEN CHILES ON IT.
THAT ROCKS.
BEST FLAVORS YOU'LL EVER
EXPERIENCE IN A PIZZA.
CRANKED OUT BY SELF-TAUGHT
PIZZA FANATIC, ROBIN HARDIE
TEAMED UP WITH
PROFESSIONAL BAKER,
PIPER KAPIN.
THEY HAVE THE BEST PIZZA
AROUND.
AND THE KEY TO THEIR PIE
IS THE CORNMEAL CRUST.
I THINK THE CRUST MAKES IT
CRISPY, BUT NOT CRUNCHY.
WE ROLL IT REALLY, REALLY THIN,
AND WE ROLL IT IN CORNMEAL.
CORNMEAL GIVES IT
A REALLY SWEET CRUNCHY FLAVOR
THAT I THINK IS BETTER
THAN FLOUR.
HANDS DOWN, I'M A CORNMEAL
CRUNCH KIND OF GUY.
LET'S GET IT ON,
START WITH THE WATER.
SO NOT COLD, THE WATER'S GOTTA
BE WARM ENOUGH
SO WE CAN ACTIVATE THE YEAST.
RIGHT, DRY YEAST, AND THEN,
GIVE IT A MINUTE
TO START DOING IT'S MAGIC.
ALL RIGHT, EXTRA VIRGIN
OLIVE OIL.
NOW, ON THE FLOUR,
HIGH GLUTEN?
HIGH GLUTEN.
SO YOU GET A NICE
STRETCH TO IT,
A NICE ELASTICITY.
SALT AND A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR.
THE SALT AND OLIVE OIL
IS WHERE YOU'RE GOING TO PICK UP
THAT FLAVOR FROM.
NOW THIS IS GOING TO RUN
FOR 15 TO 20 MINUTES.
THEN YOU CRANK UP THE SPEED
AFTER IT GETS A LITTLE
GENERAL MIX TO IT.
YES, SO FLOUR DOESN'T FLY
EVERYWHERE.
THIS LOOKS LIKE A PILLOW FIGHT
WITH ONE ALUMINUM BAT.
THERE IT IS, COVER IT UP
FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW
THAT PROOFED UP.
GET A PICTURE
NEXT TO THAT.
ABOUT 13 OUNCES OF DOUGH.
LOOK AT THIS LITTLE
TECHNIQUE THAT YOU HAVE
WHERE IT'S SPINNING FOR YOU.
HOW ARE YOU, ARE YOU
APPLYING MORE PRESSURE
ON THE RIGHT SIDE?
A LITTLE BIT MORE,
GOES AROUND.
FRESH CORNMEAL,
THIS GOES RIGHT ON HERE.
OLIVE OIL.
JUST TO BROWN IT UP
NICELY.
A FEW SESAME SEEDS.
ON EVERY PIZZA?
I DON'T THINK
I'VE SEEN THAT BEFORE.
THE SAUCE,
MOZZARELLA CHEESE.
LET'S MAKE THE TEXAN.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
ITALIAN SAUSAGE I TAKE IT.
YES.
WITH GREEN CHILE,
GIVES IT A LITTLE KICK.
MMM, IT'S DELICIOUS.
GREEN CHILE MAKES IT.
MAKES A BIG DIFFERENCE.
LOTS OF PEPPERONI,
CANADIAN BACON.
IS THIS A MEAT LOVERS DELIGHT
OR WHAT?
TEXANS LOVE IT,
THERE YOU GO.
THERE IT IS.
GOLDEN FANTASTICNESS.
WITH LASER PRECISION,
LOOK AT THAT.
THE THINNER THE BETTER,
I COULD READ THROUGH THAT,
THAT'S NICE.
NOW, HOW DO YOU EAT YOURS?
ARE YOU A FOLD OVER.
HOLD OURS STRAIGHT OUT.
YOU'RE A PINCHER?
YOU KNOW WHAT'S MISSING
RIGHT HERE?
A COLD BEER.
A BIG BEER.
EXACTLY.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU TWO ROLL.
I REALLY LIKE THIS CRUST,
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE FIRST BITE
OF THAT TEXAN?
IT'S VERY GOOD,
I LIKE THE CRUST.
THE CRUST IS GREAT
ON THE PIZZAS.
OR ANYTHING YOU PUT IN IT.
PRETTY MUCH ANYTHING
YOU PUT ON IT, I'LL EAT IT.
CALZONE COMING DOWN.
THEY USE THE SAME
PIZZA DOUGH FOR CALZONES,
GARLIC PESTO ROLLS.
REALLY GOOD.
AND EVEN THE CLASSIC
ITALIAN BRUSCHETTA.
I WANT TO MAKE
THE PENNY BRUCHETTA.
MY MOM'S NAMED PENNY.
YOUR MOM'S NAMED PENNY, SO YOU
NAMED THIS AFTER YOUR MOM?
I DID, SHE'S BEEN MAKING THIS
SINCE I WAS LITTLE.
AND THAT'S HOW IT CAME OUT?
THAT'S HOW IT CAME OUT.
OKAY, ABOUT 4 OUNCES
OF DOUGH, CORNMEAL.
YOU JUST LEAVE
A WHOLE TROUGH OF IT UP THERE.
AS MUCH AS WE CAN.
WORK OUT ALL THE AIR BUBBLES.
SO YOU ROLL THE CORNMEAL
RIGHT INTO THIS.
ARE WE GOING TO SHAKE
ANY OF THAT OFF?
NOPE, IT'LL JUST GO
RIGHT ON THERE.
OLIVE OIL,
TOMATOES, TWO.
THERE YOU GO.
KNIFE, DON'T THROW IT.
WE'LL BE HERE ALL WEEK.
SO WE CUT THE TOMATOES
TO ORDER?
YEP.
SOME ONIONS,
A TINY BIT OF GARLIC,
HOUSE MADE PESTO.
HOUSE MADE VINAIGRETTE ALSO?
ABOUT THAT MUCH,
MIX THAT ALL UP.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKING ABOUT.
THIS GOES RIGHT ON HERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF
FETA CHEESE.
JUST DUST IT?
THAT'S A PRETTY PENNY.
I'M ANTICIPATING GREATNESS
IN THIS, DRUM ROLL PLEASE.
THAT IS AWESOME.
CAN I GET THAT
AS A PIZZA?
THE WHOLE DEAL ABOUT THIS
IS THE FRESH TOMATOES,
NICE BIG PIECES OF ONION.
BUT THE KICKER IS
THE BALSAMIC,
THE HOMEMADE BALSAMIC
AND HOMEMADE PESTO.
GREAT.
THAT SHOULD BE LIKE,
HOME OF THE PENNY BRUSCHETTA.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
I LOVE THE CRUST,
THE TOMATOES AND ONIONS.
GOOD INGREDIENTS.
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S JUST REALLY GOOD
LUNCHTIME STUFF.
SO ARE THE SUBS.
HOT ITALIAN TO GO.
MORE MEAT THAN WE ACTUALLY
HAVE BUN TO PUT IT ON.
PUT THAT RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S TOO BIG.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
OH, I GET IT,
I NEED A FEED BELT.
CAN I GET A SLICE CHEESE?
HOT COMING OUT.
AT BACKROAD PIZZA
IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO...
THAT'S FOR YOU,
DARLING.
FOLKS ARE JAMMING THE JOINT
FOR PIZZA...
YOU CAN'T FINISH
THAT WHOLE THING CAN YOU?
ABSOLUTELY.
CALZONES
AND BRUSCHETTA.
I ACTUALLY DON'T LIVE HERE
AND CRAVE THIS PIZZA.
I LOVE THE THIN CRUST.
AND GET THIS.
I GOTTA A LUNCH SPECIAL
SALAD.
OWNERS ROBIN HARDIE
AND PIPER KAPIN,
DECIDED TO USE
THE SAME CRUST FOR THEIR SUBS.
LIKE THE HOT ITALIAN.
GOOD OPEN FACED SUB.
THE GREEN CHILE
ROASTED CHICKEN.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
YEP, THE ALBERT, NAMED FOR
A DUDE WHO ORDERED IT
ALMOST EVERY DAY.
TAKE ME DOWN
MEATBALL ALLEY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S START
WITH SOME EGGS.
OKAY, NOW A LITTLE
WHISKY, WHISK.
SALT, LOTS OF
GROUND PEPPER.
OREGANO.
BASIL.
HOMEMADE BREAD CRUMBS
FROM OUR BUNS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THIS MIXTURE AND PUT IT
ON TOP OF OUR BEEF.
NO PORK?
NO PORK.
NICE RED ONION.
AND THEN THE CAPITAL
OF GILROY JUMPS INTO THE POOL.
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC.
HAVE YOU BEEN THERE?
I WAS THE EMCEE OF
THE GILROY GARLIC FESTIVAL
CULINARY COMPETITION.
I USED TO TWIRL BATON
IN THEIR PARADES.
THIS IS THE BATON.
GONNA GET FLIPPED.
IS THAT HOW IT WORKS?
OKAY, WE'RE GOING
TO ROLL THIS UP.
WE'RE GOING TO PACK
THESE ROUND MEAT TREATS
NEXT TO EACH OTHER
LIKE THIS?
SEE, I LIKE THEM WHEN
THEY'RE A LITTLE BIT
SMALLER LIKE THIS,
BECAUSE I LIKE TO GET
MORE OF THE CRUNCH,
MORE OF THE TEXTURE
ON THE OUTSIDE.
OKAY, SO THESE GO DOWN.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE WHILE.
LOOK AT THOSE THINGS.
THAT'S PERFECTO.
DELICIOUS.
I LIKE THE BIG PARTS
OF THE ONION.
NOT A BUNCH OF FILLER,
ALL THRILLER.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE
GOING TO TAKE OUR MEATBALLS
THAT WE MADE EARLIER,
AND CUT THEM IN HALF
SO THEY CAN GET
NICE AND HOT AND FIT
ON THERE.
ALL THOSE ARE GOING
ON THERE?
PUTTING LOTS AND LOTS
OF SAUCE ON THERE.
CHEESE, OREGANO,
BASIL MIX.
PUT IT RIGHT HERE,
OH YEAH.
OKAY, I DON'T REALLY BELIEVE
THAT I AM GOING TO BE ABLE
TO MANAGE THIS.
THERE YOU GO, YOU GOT IT,
GET INTO IT.
VERY TASTY.
AND THE BREAD,
PERFECTLY DONE,
NICE AND CRISPY.
YOU NEED TO CREATE
SOME SORT OF SNOW SHOVEL
APPARATUS
THAT PEOPLE CAN WEAR
LIKE A TROUGH.
THAT IS GRAVITY FED
SO THAT THE SANDWICH JUST
COMES IN.
OH, I GUESS JUST PULL
THE FEED BELT.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT,
IT'S ALL FRESH INGREDIENTS.
LOTS OF LOVE,
IT'S THE BEST.
WE DON'T GO ANYWHERE ELSE.
THIS IS WHERE WE COME.
IT'S A GREAT CROWD
THAT COMES HERE.
IT'S A COOL PLACE
TO BE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT'S TRUE SANTA FE.
WE HAVE SOMETHING FOR YOU,
THE HONORARY...
SINCE YOU HELPED US...
DO I HAVE TO COME AND WORK
A SHIFT OR ANYTHING?
YES, YOU DO.
THANK YOU, LADIES.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
LOOK AT THAT,
WINNER WINNER PIZZA DINNER.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED FOR
SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪