HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
BRIAN, I GOT
YOUR CUBAN.
THIS TRIP...
VOILà.
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYWHERE.
IN FLORIDA...
IT'S A LITTLE
PIECE OF PARADISE.
THE CATERING TRUCK...
CAN WE HELP YOU?
CRANKING OUT
CUBAN FAVORITES.
MMM.
AND MEXICAN...
ONE MORE FISH TACO.
AND MORE.
THIS IS PIONONO.
OH, YO YO.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
IN SACRAMENTO...
(speaking French)
FAST FOOD...
QUICHE LORRAINE.
FROM A CHEF DOING
OLD FAMILY RECIPES...
(speaking French)
FROM BACK IN FRANCE.
CHICKEN PâTè.
MMM, PERFECT ON THE SHRIMP.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
(French accent)
NOT 12 MINUTES OR 14--
(both) 13.
AND IN IDAHO...
LAMB KABOB.
WHERE THEY'RE
DOING FAST FAVORITES.
CROQUETAS FOR YA.
BEST COMFORT FOOD.
A KIND
OF EUROPEAN COOKING...
THE GARLIC SOUP'S
SO GOOD.
(whistles)
MOST FOLKS NEVER GET
A CHANCE TO TRY.
I'M NOT MAKING THIS UP.
THIS IS TONGUE.
(normal voice) WHOA.
YUM, YUM, DOWN GOES THE TONGUE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
"ON DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO CHECK THIS OUT.
YOU EVER SEE
ONE OF THOSE TACO TRUCKS
KINDA SET UP SHOP
IN A VACANT LOT?
WELL, I'VE GOT ONE FOR YOU.
IT'S A--IT'S A--IT'S A BAR
THAT'S CATERED
BY ITS OWN CULINARY RIG
IN ITS OWN PARKING LOT
HERE IN LAKE WORTH,
FLORIDA.
NOW WE LIKE TO SAY
ON TRIPLE "D,"
IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
THIS ONE'S FUNKY, WE FOUND IT,
AND IT'S CALLED HAVANA HIDEOUT.
HERE'S YOUR PIONONO.
OKAY, VERY GOOD.
GET A LOAD OF THIS SETUP--
A FULLY LOADED
CATERING TRUCK...
CAN WE HELP YOU?
NEXT TO A DIVE BAR
WITH A TROPICAL PATIO.
YOU CAN WIGGLE
YOUR TOES IN THE SAND
LIKE YOU'RE
AT THE BEACH.
THE BEST SANGRIA
AND THE BEST TACOS.
ALL OWNED BY CALI GIRL,
CHRISSY BENOIT...
HOW YOU DOIN'?
WHO LEFT THE BUSINESS SIDE
OF HIGH-END RESTAURANTS...
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
AND STARTED MAKING
THE FOOD SHE LOVES.
BRIAN, HERE'S
YOUR SAMPLER.
I WANTED TO DO STREET FOOD
BECAUSE I THINK IT'S GOT SOUL.
THREE EMPANADAS, PLEASE,
STUFF FROM PUERTO RICO,
BAJA, CALIFORNIA.
THE FISH TACOS,
THEY'RE REALLY INCREDIBLE.
CUBAN FOOD.
CUBAN SANDWICH
IS PERFECT, MMM.
AND SHE'S DOING
THIS CLASSIC...
BRIAN,
I GOT YOUR CUBAN.
TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH.
WE ARE ROASTING
THE GARLIC PORK,
AND THIS IS THE PORK
THAT WE USE IN ALL THE CUBANS.
OKAY, PORK BUTT...
CUT INTO THE PORK
JUST TO CREATE SOME CREVICES.
LITTLE ANGER OR AGGRESSION
ISSUE THING GOING ON HERE?
NO.
TAKE A BUNCH OF GARLIC. WE'RE
GONNA STUFF ALL THESE HOLES
AND THEN JUST
SCHMEAR IT ALL OVER.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE SALT
ON TOP OF THE FAT CAP.
YEAH, I TRY
TO DO A GENEROUS AMOUNT,
SO IT REALLY PULLS
THE FLAVORS ON IT.
JUST COVER IT UP
WITH SOME FOIL,
AND WE DO
THE LOW AND SLOW METHOD--
7 HOURS, 250 DEGREES,
TURN IT AND LET IT GO.
THE UNVEILING.
LET IT COOL DOWN A LITTLE BIT
SO YOU CAN MESS WITH IT.
YES, EXACTLY.
OKAY, IS IT DONE?
UH, YEAH, I THINK WHEN THE BONE
COMES OUT THAT LICKETY-SPLIT.
MMM.
WE JUST KINDA START
PULLING IT APART.
GOT GOOD MOISTURE.
LOOK AT THESE LITTLE GARLIC
POCKETS RIGHT IN THERE.
HURRY UP WITH IT, BECAUSE IF
I KEEP SITTING HERE,
YOU'RE GONNA BE
ONE LESS PORK BUTT.
YEAH.
NICE-LOOKING BAGUETTE.
CUT 'EM OPEN.
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
LOTS OF NICE TART MUSTARD.
THANK YOU.
SEE THAT? SAME TEAM.
THEN WE ARE GONNA LAYER IT
WITH DILL PICKLE SLICES.
WOW, A LITTLE
PICKLE-ISTIC.
YEP, SLICES OF HAM,
END-TO-END WITH HAM.
(foreign accent) SORRY, CLOSED.
NO SOUP FOR YOU.
(laughs)
NICE AMOUNT
OF PULLED PORK.
(normal voice)
I'M SPOTTING YOU.
RIGHT.
(Russian accent) YOU CAN
DO IT, YEAH. KEEP GOING.
GET THE SPOT GOIN'. HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC SALT.
WE USE MOZZARELLA.
(normal voice)
MOZZARELLA?
MM-HMM.
A TRUE
CUBAN SANDWICH--SWISS.
SWISS, I KNOW.
WHAT'S GOIN' ON?
WE LIKE THE FLAVOR
OF THE MOZZARELLA.
SANDWICH WRECKER.
SANDWICH INNOVATOR.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT INTO FOUR.
SO AS OPPOSED TO MAKING
A BUNCH OF 'EM INDIVIDUALLY,
YOU JUST MAKE ONE
BIG MONGO AT A TIME.
EXACTLY.
OKAY.
RUB 'EM WITH BUTTER.
THEN WE USE LANDSCAPING BRICKS
AND WE WEIGH 'EM DOWN.
CULINARY SPECIALTY BRICKS.
YES.
READY TO FLIP?
YEP.
I SHALL PULL
THE CULINARY BRICK. HA HA!
TEN MINUTES IN TOTAL?
CORRECT.
MMM.
TAKE 'EM OFF.
HOLY FLAT, BATMAN.
RIGHT.
OW, WHOA.
IT'S HOT. I'M SORRY.
NO PLATES?
WHAT, YOU JUST GIVE IT
PEOPLE OUT THE WINDOW?
HERE YOU GO!
YEAH.
MMM. OH, A NAPKIN,
THANK YOU.
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
MOZZARELLA HAS A GOOD AMOUNT
OF SALT TO IT.
YEAH.
SO I THINK THAT FORTIFIES
WITH A LITTLE SALT.
THE CRUNCH
ON THE BREAD IS LIKE--
CAN YOU HEAR IT?
THE ONLY THING THAT
I THINK THE SANDWICH MISSES
IS THE TANG
OF THE SWISS.
WHY--
THE PULLED PORK MAKES IT.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE
IN THE TOP FIVE.
THANK YOU.
REALLY GOOD JOB.
THANKS.
THE TASTE IS EXCELLENT.
THE MEAT'S NICE AND SAVORY.
THE CHEESE IS CREAMY.
PICKLES AND EVERYTHING,
IT'S PERFECT.
FOOD IS DEFINITELY
AN A-PLUS.
NO, STOP IT.
IT'S VERY LAID BACK,
BEACH ATMOSPHERE,
LIKE SOMEWHERE
IN PUERTO RICO.
ENJOY A CIGAR, A LITTLE
GLASS OF WINE AND GOOD FOOD.
OKAY, ROCK 'N' ROLL.
EVERY TIME I TRAVEL,
I'M THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT EATS
RIGHT OFF THE CARTS.
CHIPS.
AND NOW THEY ARE.
SEVICHE.
THE FRESH SALSA,
FRESH FISH.
BEEF EMPANADAS.
ALL RIGHT.
THE FISH TACOS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A PICTURE
RIGHT THERE.
MMM, I GOTTA TELL YA, THAT
TASTES AS GOOD AS IT LOOKS.
AND THE NEWEST HIT
ON THE MENU,
CHRISSY'S TAKE
ON A PUERTO RICAN FAVORITE.
THIS IS PIONONO.
OH, YO YO.
I TRIED IT IN PUERTO RICO
OFF A STREET VENDOR.
DOWN THERE, IT'S USUALLY
A FRIED, STUFFED PLANTAIN...
PIONONO.
BUT CHRISSY'S TURNED IT
INTO SOMETHING ALL HER OWN.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE A LASAGNA,
SHEPHERD'S PIE...
EXACTLY.
SO HOW
DO WE START IT?
DO A QUICK SAUTé
ON THE VEG OIL--
WHITE ONIONS,
MIXED BELL PEPPERS, TOMATOES.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS GOING.
A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC.
SO BASICALLY WHAT WE'D CALL
THAT IS A LITTLE SOFRITO.
YEAH.
JUST GONNA COOK
THIS FOR A SECOND.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
TAKE THE BEEF.
LET IT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER DOWN, OKAY.
MM-HMM AND ADD SALT,
VINEGAR...
VINEGAR,
TOMATO PASTE.
TOMATO PASTE,
RAISINS.
THERE'S A REASON
FOR RAISINS.
GREEN OLIVES,
A LITTLE RED CHILI PEPPER,
GIVE A LITTLE KICK.
WOW, PEPPER.
BLACK PEPPER.
ACHIOTE PASTE--
COMING FROM THE ANNATTO SEED.
MM-HMM, IT'S A REALLY
NICE EARTHY FLAVOR.
ONCE THIS IS ALL COOKED,
WE LAYER IT IN A PAN WITH
A MIXTURE OF YELLOW PLANTAINS,
ADD A LITTLE BUTTER,
SQUISH 'EM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
AND A LITTLE
PASTEURIZED EGG.
JUST A LITTLE.
HOLDS IT TOGETHER,
I DIG YA.
MM-HMM. I'VE GOT, YOU KNOW,
1/4-INCH OF PLANTAIN
AND THEN DUMP
THE MEAT ON IT.
FANTASTIC.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
BUILDING A LASAGNA.
WE'RE GONNA SPRINKLE
THE TOP OF THIS
WITH SOME GRATED
PARMESAN CHEESE.
IT'S TWO BEEF LAYERS
AND THREE PLANTAIN LAYERS.
MORE EGG ON TOP, MAKE SURE
TO PULL IT TOGETHER.
POP IT IN THE OVEN FOR LIKE
35 MINUTES, ABOUT 300 DEGREES.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THIS. WHOA, THAT--
WE GET NINE SERVINGS
OUT OF THIS PAN,
SO THEY'RE PRETTY
DECENT-SIZED PIECES.
YEAH, YOU DO.
WOW. YOU KNOW
HOW GOOD THAT IS?
THAT BEEF MIXTURE
IS JUST ON POINT.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE PLANTAIN
TIES RIGHT IN.
IT'S CREAMY, SALTY,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
IT'S GOT ALL OF THE FLAVOR
COMPONENTS THAT YOU WANT.
I MEAN,
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TERRIFIC, VERY SPICY.
ONE MORE FISH TACO.
(man) THERE'S
SOMETHING UNIQUE.
ANYTIME OF THE DAY,
THEY'LL SERVE YOU A GREAT MEAL.
EATING OUTSIDE'S
LIKE MY FAVORITE THING.
THE ATMOSPHERE
IS KILLER.
CHRISSY DOES AN AMAZING JOB
OF MAKING YOU FEEL AT HOME.
HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S A LITTLE PIECE
OF PARADISE RIGHT HERE.
GIRL, NOW
THIS LITTLE HUT--
YOU'RE CRANKING OUT
SOME KILLER GRINDS.
THANK YOU.
NOW WHEN THE LINE
STARTS FORMING,
I WANT MY STUFF
OUT THE BACK DOOR.
OKAY.
UP NEXT...
HA HA!
WE'RE HEADING
TO NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
BON APPéTIT!
EVERY TIME I COME IN HERE,
I TRY SOMETHING NEW.
FOR FAVORITES...
VOILà.
FROM THE SOUTH OF FRANCE.
MMM, THAT IS
REALLY GOOD.
SO HERE'S ONE FOR YA.
DID YOU KNOW THAT I WAS
AN EXCHANGE STUDENT IN FRANCE
WHEN I WAS
IN HIGH SCHOOL, HUH?
WELL, ANYHOW, I DON'T KNOW
THAT EVERYBODY REALLY GETS
THE FRENCH FOOD EXPERIENCE LIKE
I DID WHEN I LIVED THERE.
SO I'M HERE IN EAST SACRAMENTO
AT A PLACE CALLED CAFE ROLLE
TO GET MY FRENCH FOOD FIX.
(speaks French)...
QUICHE LORRAINE.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
EVERY TIME I COME IN HERE
I TRY SOMETHING NEW.
MOUSSE AU CHOCOLATE.
THIS IS LIKE
A PARIS BISTRO.
BON APPéTIT.
ALL THE HERBS,
THE FLAVORS.
VOILà.
REMINDS ME
OF BEING IN FRANCE.
BONJOUR, MONSIEUR!
AND IT OUGHT TO...
CHICKEN PâTé APPETIZER!
'CAUSE WILLIAM ROLLE
GREW UP THERE...
HE'S FROM
FRANCE ORIGINALLY.
IN LYON, WHERE HIS PARENTS RAN
WHAT'S CALLED A TRAITEUR.
THAT'S THE FRENCH VERSION
OF A DELI...
AND I ARRIVED HERE
TEN YEARS AGO.
AND OPENED UP A PLACE
JUST LIKE MOM AND DAD'S.
WE DO THE SAME RECIPES
FROM SCRATCH AT A DECENT PRICE.
(speaks French)
FAST FOOD
THE FRENCH WAY...
VOILà.
THAT MEANS TOPPING SALAD
WITH QUICHE.
BON APPéTIT.
A GRILLED HAM AND CHEESE
LOOK LIKE THIS.
(woman) WARM FRENCH HAM
WITH MELTED GRUYERE CHEESE.
THE CROQUE MONSIEUR?
THAT'S CORRECT.
AND PâTé...
PâTé SANDWICH.
IS ALWAYS ON THE MENU.
PEOPLE WANT
TO ASK ME, WHAT IS PâTé?
I'M LIKE
FRENCH MEATLOAF.
FRENCH MEATLOAF!
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
CHICKEN PâTé.
CHICKEN PâTé WITH
GOAT CHEESE, OKAY.
OKAY, THE BOWL,
SPECIAL BREAD WITH POTATO SKIN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SOAK IT
IN LOW-FAT..
LOW-FAT.
HALF-AND-HALF CREAM.
OKAY, CHICKEN.
HOW DID THE CHICKEN
GET COOKED?
WE USE PROVENçAL,
SALT AND OIL
FOR 20 MINUTES.
SO CHICKEN, SLICE IT,
DA-NA! LIKE THAT.
THEN UN...
DEUX.
TROIS. ALL RIGHT, LET'S
GO SEE THE BIG BOWL.
THIS GUY'S NUTS.
NOW THAT'S
A SERIOUS GRINDER.
OKAY, SHOWTIME.
(scats)
ALL RIGHT, PARSLEY
AND THEN GOAT CHEESE
AND THEN...
OKAY.
WE MIX IT.
WITH...
YOUR FOOT?
I BE BACK!
(whistling)
ALL RIGHT,
THEN WE MIX IT.
NOW IT GOES
IN THE OVEN.
GOES IN THE OVEN.
350?
45 MINUTES.
AS SOON AS THE TOP
IS BROWN, IT'S DONE.
MAYBE I SHOULD PUT IT ON
A STICK AND SELL IT AT THE FAIR.
EH, NOT A BAD IDEA.
YEAH.
SO WE'RE DONE,
WE'RE COOLED.
WE CUT IT
TO GET OUT. HA HA!
LITTLE BAGUETTE,
LITTLE MUSTARD AND VOILà.
MMM, THAT
IS REALLY GOOD.
GREAT FLAVOR,
REAL NICE AND MOIST.
THE COMBINATION BETWEEN
THE HERBES DE PROVENCE,
THE GOAT CHEESE
AND THE CHICKEN,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE PARSLEY--EXCELLENT.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
THAT YOU CAN GET IT.
THE QUALITY OF THE FOOD
FOR THE PRICE...
I'M PLEASANTLY
SURPRISED.
NO WONDER THE OFFICE
LUNCH CROWD IS PACKING IN.
SHE CAME BACK TO WORK
AND WAS JUST RAVING
ABOUT THE RESTAURANT.
(speaking French)
THEY LOVE IT!
GETTING ME INTO FRENCH FOOD,
WHICH I NEVER HAVE BEEN BEFORE.
IT TASTES, YOU KNOW,
LIKE IT DOES OVER THERE.
WHEN I LIVED IN FRANCE, THE WAY
I WOULD EAT WAS A LOT LIKE THIS.
YES.
(woman) IT'S A LOT
OF SALADS,
A LOT OF COLD SANDWICHES
AND SMALL DISHES.
(Guy) I THINK WHEN MOST PEOPLE
THINK FRENCH RESTAURANT,
THEY THINK ESCARGOT, THEY THINK
EVERYTHING IS BIG AND RICH.
YEAH, THIS IS MORE
COUNTRY STYLE, CASUAL STYLE.
THE WAY WILLIAM LEARNED
FROM HIS FOLKS BACK IN LYON...
OKAY, IS IT
READY TO GO?
OH, YEAH!
LIKE SMOKIN' SALMON
FROM HIS DAD'S OWN RECIPE.
MY DAD TEACH ME.
AND YOU'RE MAKING SALMON
ALL THE TIME?
ALL THE TIME.
THAT'S MY SPECIALTY.
60 POUNDS A WEEK,
SMOKED OVER HICKORY
AND SLICED BY HAND.
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE,
A LITTLE DILL...
LITTLE DILL, CRèME FRAîCHE,
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED. GOOD, HUH?
THE DILL--DELICIOUS.
OH, YEAH.
I'M TELLING YOU,
IT'S WONDERFUL.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S REALLY FRESH.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S
WHAT YOU GET IN FRANCE,
JUST SIMPLE, FRESH FOOD.
LIKE THIS CLASSIC LENTIL
VINAIGRETTE SALAD FROM LYON...
VERY FAMILIAR.
THAT WILLIAM'S TOPPING
WITH ROASTED PRAWNS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE MARINADE
FROM "LON-TIL."
LENTIL!
LENTIL SALADE!
FIRST, WE GET
THE LENTIL.
JUST REGULAR LENTIL.
REGULAR LENTIL! YOU DON'T
EVEN HAVE TO BE FRENCH.
THEN CHICKEN STOCK.
YES.
THEN WINE.
DON'T PUT
TOO MUCH WINE IN--1 CUP.
THAT'S A LOT MORE
THAN 1 CUP.
THERE WE GO--
A FRENCH CUP.
AND A LITTLE
OF THE PROVENCE AND VOILà.
WE PUT IT ON THE STOVE
FOR 20 MINUTES. UP.
NOW...
WE NEED THE PRAWNS,
SOME PROVENçAL.
LAVENDER, THYME, BASIL.
DIRECTLY FROM FRANCE...
MMM.
SO THE GOOD STUFF.
SMELLS FANTASTIC.
THEN...
SOME SHALLOTS, OKAY.
SOME GARLIC,
SOME PARSLEY.
THAT'S INTERESTING,
YOU'RE USING CURLY PARSLEY
VERSUS FLAT-LEAF.
YEAH, IN FRANCE THAT'S WHAT
WE USE, AND I'M USED TO IT.
OKAY.
AND THEN OIL.
AND THIS IS GONNA BE
THE MARINADE FOR THE SHRIMP?
WE PUT IT IN THE OVEN
300 FAHRENHEIT.
HOW LONG?
13 MINUTES.
NOT 12, NOT 14--13.
OUR LENTILS HAVE COOKED DOWN.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
ADD THE LIQUID.
THIS IS DIJON MUSTARD...
DIJON MUSTARD.
SOYBEAN OIL AND A LITTLE BIT
OF RED WINE VINEGAR.
THEN SOME PROVENçAL,
SALT,
THEN STIR.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT THE SHRIMP
ON TOP OF THE COLD LENTIL SALAD.
YES. EH, VOILà.
MMM, PERFECT ON THE SHRIMP.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
(French accent)
NOT 12 MINUTES, NOT 14...
(both) 13.
(normal voice) MMM, THE DIJON
VINAIGRETTE COATS IT NICELY.
BLENDED TOGETHER, IT'S SEGMENTED
FROM FLAVORS AND TEXTURES.
THE HERBES DE PROVENCE
TAKE A VERY FLORAL NOTE.
BACK THAT
TAPE UP A SECOND.
FLORAL NOTE.
YEP, I SAID FLORAL NOTE.
IT HAS A LOT OF FLAVOR,
SO THE SHRIMP COOKED PERFECTLY.
THE FOOD IS WONDERFUL.
COMING HERE,
THEY SPEAK FRENCH...
BON APPéTIT!
FUN ATMOSPHERE
WITH GREAT FOOD.
I BRING SOMEBODY NEW
HERE EVERY WEEK.
REALLY?
I DO.
(scats)
AMERICAN PEOPLE LOVE THE FOOD.
THEY CAN'T WAIT TO COME BACK.
HE'S GOT
SO MUCH PERSONALITY.
IT BRINGS US
COMING BACK EVERY TIME.
THIS IS REALLY HOW HE IS.
THIS IS NOT A SHOW.
YOU GOTTA
COME WATCH THIS.
(singing in French)
NEXT STOP, IDAHO...
CROQUETAS FOR YOU.
FOR A KIND
OF COOKIN'...
(whistles)
MOST FOLKS HAVE
NEVER TRIED.
IF YOU'RE IN BOISE
AND YOU HAVEN'T HAD BASQUE FOOD,
YOU'VE BEEN
LIVING UNDER A ROCK?
PRETTY MUCH.
SO CHECK THIS OUT.
IT TAKES ME COMIN' ALL THE WAY
TO BOISE, IDAHO, TO FIND
THE LARGEST BASQUE POPULATION
IN THE UNITED STATES.
NOW THE BASQUE
ARE AN ETHNIC GROUP
WITH THEIR OWN
LANGUAGE AND HISTORY,
AND THEY COME FROM PROVINCES
SPANNING THE BORDER
BETWEEN FRANCE AND SPAIN.
NOW THEY'VE GOT
THEIR OWN STYLE
AND DEFINITELY
THEIR OWN CUISINE,
AND THAT BRINGS ME HERE
TO THE BASQUE BLOCK
AND THIS JOINT,
BAR GERNIKA.
LAMB KABOB CROQUETAS.
IT'S LIKE A BASQUE,
BOISE SECRET.
I LIKE THE BASQUE FOOD,
I LIKE LAMB.
WE'VE GOT GRINDER UP.
THIS IS ONE
OF THE MOST AUTHENTIC.
WELL, IF IT WASN'T
THE BASQUES, WOULDN'T COME.
IF YOU'RE IN BOISE
AND YOU HAVEN'T HAD BASQUE FOOD,
YOU'VE BEEN LIVING
UNDER A ROCK?
PRETTY MUCH.
SO BASQUE FOOD
IS WHAT KIND OF FOOD?
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
SIMPLE INGREDIENTS,
GOOD, HOME, EARTHY COOKING.
THAT CHEF MAY LEARNED
IN TEN YEARS OF WORKING
WITH THE ORIGINAL
BASQUE OWNER.
AND THEN YOU BOUGHT IT?
YEAH, I BOUGHT IT
LAST YEAR.
AND HE'S KEEPING
THE TRADITION GOING
WITH ALL KINDS
OF FAST CLASSICS.
THE CROQUETAS ARE PROBABLY
THE MOST AMAZING FOOD HERE.
THE GARLIC SOUP
IS JUST SO GOOD.
AND ESPECIALLY THIS MARINATED
PORK AND PEPPER SANDWICH
CALLED A SOLOMO.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT ONE.
THIS IS A TRADITIONAL
BASQUE DISH?
TRADITIONAL BASQUE.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE IT
WITH SOME CHERESETO PEPPERS
THAT WE'VE RECONSTITUTED.
CHERESETO?
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE
EVER SEEN A CHERESETO PEPPER.
SWEET PEPPER.
REALLY?
A LOT OF THE OLD-TIMERS
BROUGHT OVER SEEDS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A SAUCE OUT OF IT, I TAKE IT?
YEP, WE RUN THAT THROUGH
THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
NOW RUN IT THROUGH
THE FOOD MILL.
GET THE SKINS
AND THE SEEDS OFF OF IT.
SO YOU GET THIS SAUCE,
AND THIS IS GONNA GO WHERE?
A CENTER-CUT
PORK LOIN
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT TO IT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
POUR THE PEPPER SAUCE
ON THERE.
PEPPER SAUCE ON TOP OF IT,
MARINATE IT AND THEN--
YEP, WE'RE GONNA
MARINATE IT OVERNIGHT.
YOU'RE MAKING 'EM ALL THE TIME.
YOU HAVE 'EM FOR THE NEXT DAY.
YEAH.
SO CUT SLICES OFF IT?
YEP, THROW A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL DOWN, FRY THAT UP.
GOTTA LOVE THE FLAT TOP.
THESE ARE PIMENTOS?
THEY'RE COOKED WITH SAUTéED
GARLIC, SALT
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR.
ADD A LITTLE
PIMENTO JUICE.
MMM,
I'M DIGGIN' THAT.
THEY'RE READY TO FLIP.
MMM.
A LITTLE MORE
PIMENTO JUICE.
(whistles)
IT'S A NICE-LOOKING
BAGUETTE.
THERE IS SOME GOOD BREAD
HERE IN BOISE.
REALLY?
PIMENTOS ON THERE,
GOOD STUFF.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT,
AT THE JUICY GOODNESS DRIPPING
OUT OF THERE.
MMM, WOW,
RIGHT ON, MAN.
YOU GOT SWEETNESS, TEXTURE,
TENDERNESS OF THE MEAT,
A NICE,
STURDY BAGUETTE.
THAT'S GREAT, MMM.
SOLOMO?
SOLOMO, YEAH.
SO LONG, SOLOMO. MMM!
IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITES HERE.
I HAVE THAT
A LOT WHEN I COME.
I ALWAYS GET A SOLOMO.
IT'S GREAT.
ALL RIGHT.
I JUST REALLY ENJOY
THE FOOD, ALL OF IT.
THEY HAVE SOME
GOOD AUTHENTIC DISHES.
CROQUETAS FOR YOU.
YOU'VE GROWN UP
WITH THIS?
OH, YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S A MAINSTAY.
ESPECIALLY
ON THIS BLOCK.
AND THEY DO CALL IT
THE BASQUE BLOCK?
THIS IS THE BASQUE BLOCK.
WHY BOISE?
IT WAS JUST A PIPELINE.
SOMEONE CAME AND SAID,
HEY, COME HERD SHEEP WITH US,
AND ALL
THE BASQUES CAME.
SO YOU SEE LAMB
ON THE MENU.
LIKE THE HOMEMADE LAMB STEW,
MARINATED GRILL LAMB...
AND LAMB KABOB.
INTERESTING SPICES.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND A BIG FAVORITE HERE...
MMM, LAMB GRINDER.
(Chef May) WE SELL
A COUPLE HUNDRED OF THOSE A DAY.
SO THIS IS JUST OUR LITTLE TAKE
ON A LAMB SANDWICH.
WE'RE GONNA START OUT
WITH SOME TRIMMED-OUT
BONELESS LEG OF LAMB,
ADD SOME SALT.
KOSHER?
DO A LITTLE GRANULATED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE
WHITE WINE.
JUST ENOUGH
TO THROW SOME FLAVOR
BUT NOT WASH OFF
THE SEASONING.
WE'RE GONNA THROW THIS
IN THE OVEN, 400 DEGREES,
90 MINUTES.
BIG QUARTERS HERE.
DO YOU HAVE TO GET
MEASUREMENTS ON PEOPLE
BEFORE THEY GET
A JOB COOKING HERE?
YEAH. PULL THE LAMB
OUT OF THE OVEN.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
HALFWAY THROUGH,
ADD IN A TOUCH MORE WINE.
ALL RIGHT. MMM.
SO YOU GET ALL THE FUN
OFF THE BOTTOM OF THAT,
MAKE A LITTLE
GRAVY FOR THIS.
A LITTLE
AU JUS, EXACTLY.
SO THAT'S GOT THE SALT,
PEPPER, A LITTLE BIT
OF GRANULATED GARLIC
AND THE WHITE WINE...
YEAH.
AND ALSO THE DRIPPINGS
FROM THE LAMB.
A LITTLE
RED WINE FLAVOR.
BEEF STOCK.
AND A LITTLE WATER.
WE'LL LET THAT COOK DOWN
FOR JUST A LITTLE BIT.
SAUTé UP GREEN PEPPERS,
ONIONS, MUSHROOMS,
A LITTLE CORNSTARCH.
TIGHTEN IT
UP A BIT.
YEAH.
SO WE'VE GOT THE AU JUS,
ONIONS, PEPPERS AND MUSHROOM.
A LITTLE SHERRY.
AND LAMB.
SLICES HERE,
THAT'S JUST THE BEST PART.
SOMETHING SO SIMPLE
AND SEASONED SO MILDLY
TASTES SO AWESOME.
YEAH, IT DOESN'T TAKE MUCH.
LITTLE BIT OF LOVE.
LAYER THAT ON,
CHEESE.
A LITTLE SAUCE ON THERE
TO HELP MELT THE CHEESE UP.
THROW A LITTLE STEAM,
THROW YOUR BUCKET ON TOP.
MM-HMM.
I LIKE THE WAY
THAT'S LOOKING, MAN.
OH, YEAH.
OH, DIG IT.
GIVE YOU
A LITTLE SAUCE.
OH, YOU GET AU JUS
ON THE SIDE.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
COOKED THE LAMB PERFECT,
JUICY, NICE TEXTURE.
OHH, REALLY TENDER,
GREAT FLAVOR,
BUT THE KICKER HERE
IS THE AU JUS.
MAN, THAT'S NICE. MMM.
NICE JOB ON THAT.
YOU KNOW, YOU JUST CAN'T GO
WRONG WITH IT. IT'S JUST GREAT.
THIS IS ALL
I EVER EAT.
YEAH.
THEY DO AN AMAZING
JOB WITH IT.
SANDWICH
FOR MAC AND KARA.
FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU.
GRINDER.
AND YOU DRINK THIS CRAZY DRINK
WITH HALF RED WINE, HALF SODA.
CALIMOCHOS.
IT HURTS.
BUT IT MIGHT BE JUST
THE THING TO WASH DOWN
THIS WEEKLY SPECIAL...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
FOLKS ARE PACKING IN FOR.
I'M NOT MAKING THIS UP.
THIS IS TONGUE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IN THIS CONTAINER
TONGUE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YOU WANT A BITE?
SO WELCOME BACK.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
WHAT'S IN THE POT?
MARVELOUS BEEF TONGUE.
YOU CAME BACK FOR THIS.
TO BAR GERNIKA
IN BOISE, IDAHO,
WHERE REAL-DEAL BASQUE COOKING
MEANS MARINATED PORK,
CHICKEN CROQUETAS,
GRILLED LAMB.
QUITE AUTHENTIC.
AUTHENTIC? YOU THINK?
I WOULD LOOK
AT THE USE OF TONGUE
JUST LIKE
THAT WITH LIVER.
LIVING IN POOR TIMES,
YOUR FAMILY RAISED THE ONE COW.
YEAH.
YOU GOTTA FIGURE OUT SOMETHING
TO DO WITH EVERYTHING.
EXACTLY, SO THIS IS JUST A WAY
TO NOT WASTE ANY OF THE MEAT.
RIGHT.
WHAT WAS IT
DOING IN THE POT?
WELL, WE BOILED IT FOR
ABOUT FOUR OR FIVE HOURS,
KINDA GET IT A LITTLE
MORE TENDER, SKIN IT.
OKAY. WHOA.
IT'S REALLY, UH--
PUNGENT?
MM-HMM. HOW DID IT
BECOME PART OF THE MENU HERE?
THE FORMER OWNER'S MOM
USED TO MAKE IT EVERY SATURDAY,
SO IT'S JUST
BEEN A TRADITION.
WE USUALLY START
SERVING IT ABOUT 11:30,
AND MOST OF THE TIME,
WE CAN RUN OUT BY 1:00...
OH, I BET YOU DO.
2:00.
TONGUE. (gulping)
YOU JUST WANT
TO SLICE IT UP THICK.
MMM, LOOKS LIKE
TONGUE BALONEY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF KOSHER SALT TO IT,
GRANULATED GARLIC, JUST ADD
A LITTLE MORE FLAVOR.
THAT TONGUE
KNOWS FLAVOR.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
GOOD GRASSY FLAVOR.
MM-HMM.
WELL, NOW
WE GOTTA BREAD IT,
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE FLOUR.
PLEASE TELL ME WE'RE
FRYING THIS THING.
OH, YEAH.
PLEASE TELL--OH, GOOD.
A LITTLE OIL.
IS THAT JUST GONNA BE
THE EGG ON THE OUTSIDE?
THERE'S NO MORE FLOUR?
NOPE.
HMM, GOOD.
DON'T HOLD BACK.
YES, YES.
NO, IT IS, IT'S LIKE
FRENCH TOAST TONGUE.
OH, WATCH OUT.
OH, OH, BURN! OH,
I GOTTA GO HOME, GOTTA LEAVE.
I'M TRAUMATIZED.
SO WHAT HAPPENS HERE
AFTER WE FRY THESE UP?
WE'RE GONNA
PUT THIS IN A SAUCE--
OLIVE OIL,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
ONION AND GARLIC PURéE,
TONGUE BITS.
SOME OF THE CHERESETO PEPPER
SAUCE GROUND UP INTO IT.
MMM.
SALT, PAPRIKA,
TOMATO SAUCE,
LITTLE TONGUE MARINARA.
SITS THERE AND MARINATES,
KINDA WITH THE SAUCE.
OH, THAT'S GOOD, GOOD.
I'M DRIVING.
ALL RIGHT.
OOH.
EYES ARE BIGGER
THAN MY TONGUE.
OOH.
THEY'RE ROLLIN' OFF
THE TONGUE TODAY.
THEY ARE.
IT'S HOT, I BET.
I'M LETTIN' IT COOL DOWN.
MMM, WOW.
WHAT DO YOU OF THAT?
IT'S FANTASTIC.
YEAH.
THE TONGUE, THAT IS TENDER.
IT'S LIKE ROAST BEEF.
THAT PAPRIKA, TOMATO,
GARLIC SAUCE IS OFF THE CHAIN.
YUM, YUM,
DOWN GOES THE TONGUE.
MMM, REALLY GOOD SAUCE.
THIS IS THE OWNER'S MOM'S RECIPE
THAT SHE USED TO DOWN HERE?
UH-HUH.
SO WHEN
PEOPLE COME DOWN,
THEY'RE GETTING IT
THE LEGIT WAY.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
AND IT'S
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
IT'S A SPECIALTY.
IT'S HEAVEN.
SOLOMO'S READY.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THE FOOD HERE,
IT IS THE BEST COMFORT FOOD.
AND IT'S LIKE
COMING INTO A FRIEND'S HOUSE.
WE HAVE GUESTS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD.
WE BRING 'EM HERE.
THIS IS A VERY INTERESTING
RESTAURANT, YOU KNOW THAT?
I STILL TELL YA,
THOUGH, LAMB GRINDER--
OKAY, NOW I ATE
MY TONGUE.
CAN I HAVE A SPICY
LAMB GRINDER, PLEASE?
YEAH.
PLEASE,
I ATE THE TONGUE.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON TRIPLE "D"--
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WANT TO TRY A BITE?
WE ALWAYS FEED THE CAMERA.
THEY GET REALLY HAPPY.
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
IS THAT KILLER OR WHAT?
VERY HAPPY, GOOD CAMERA.
GO LAY DOWN.
(whimpers)