HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
CHOCOLATE SAUCE.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
EVERYTHING HAS
UNIQUE INGREDIENTS.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
DOING IT THEIR OWN WAY...
BOURBON, BOURBON,
WHISKEY, WHISKEY?
WE LIKE TO SHOCK.
I LOVE FLAMES.
IN CHICAGO...
IT'S NOT YOUR EVERYDAY
JOE BURGER.
AT A DIVE BAR...
INCREDIBLY UNIQUE.
WHERE THEY'RE
NAMING BURGERS...
METALLICA.
FOR HEAVY METAL BANDS.
BLACK SABBATH BURGER.
MMM.
AND THEY'LL TOP 'EM
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
(woman) BRIE CHEESE
AND A POACHED PEAR.
MMM.
WOW.
IN FLAGSTAFF, ARIZONA...
LIME CHICKEN'S
BEING PLATED.
IT'S ALWAYS WONDERFUL.
YOU DOING OKAY
OVER HERE?
A LOCAL PLACE...
IT'S GOT
THE HOMETOWN FEEL.
LIKE A BIG FAMILY
IN HERE.
WITH A GLOBE-TROTTIN' CHEF...
OKAY, I LEARNED THIS
IN COSTA RICA.
WHO'S GOT HIS OWN PLAN
FOR DINNER.
(Guy) MADE TO ORDER
AND STEW DON'T GO TOGETHER.
I DON'T LIKE ANYTHING
SITTIN' IN POTS.
AND IN SAN DIEGO...
THEIR MOTTO IS "ALL WE DO IS
FISH," AND THAT'S ALL THEY DO.
THE SEAFOOD JOINT...
GUYS--THEY KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
WHERE IT'S FRESH...
YOU'RE BREAKING THE FISH
DOWN 100%. I LOVE IT.
AND FAST...
WE DO EVERYTHING
ON THE GRILL.
AND A LOCAL FAVORITE.
REALLY CAN'T BEAT IT.
YOU GOT A PhD
AT THE COLLEGE BY THE SEA,
DR. FISH TACO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, BURGERS ARE
KIND OF LIKE THE PLACES
WE VISIT HERE ON THREE "D."
WELL, YOU GOT YOUR BASIC.
NOW YOU GOT YOUR CLASSICS.
AND THEN YOU GOT THOSE JOINTS
THAT ARE KINDA PUSHIN'
THE ENVELOPE,
KIND OF LIKE THIS PLACE,
KUMA'S CORNER IN CHICAGO,
WHERE THEY'RE SERIOUS ON INK,
HEAVY METAL
AND BODACIOUS BURGERS.
THERE'S SOMETHIN' SPECIAL
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
THEIR BURGERS
ARE THE BEST.
MMM.
EVERYTHING HAS
A UNIQUE INGREDIENT ON IT.
(Guy) BRATS.
HERE YOU GET THINGS
LIKE PULLED PORK,
NEON GREEN RELISH.
(woman) BRIE CHEESE
AND A POACHED PEAR.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S NOT YOUR EVERYDAY
JOE BURGER.
AND THE OWNER'S
NOT YOUR EVERYDAY JOE...
THIS IS ME--
BIKER THAT OWNS A BAR.
WITH PLENTY OF INK...
METALLICA.
AND BURGERS NAMED
FOR HEAVY METAL BANDS.
THE METALLICA BURGER
HAS BUFFALO SAUCE
AND BLUE CHEESE DRESSING
AND BACON.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE ROLLIN'
A SLAYER BURGER--
CHILI, ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE,
CHEESE, ONIONS--FANTASTIC.
AND A CHILI-CHEESE-ONION BURGER
CALLED...
THE BLACK SABBATH BURGER.
A FAN FAVORITE...
THANK YOU.
THAT HEAD CHEF
AMALIA OBERMEIER-SMITH
IS CRANKIN' OUT
BY THE DOZEN.
ORDER UP!
IT'S A LITTLE BIT MESSY,
BUT IT'S FANTASTIC.
OKAY, WE'LL MAKE
SOME CHILI.
YES.
(whistles) GOT THE WHOLE
KITCHEN CABINET HERE.
WALK ME THROUGH.
OLIVE OIL.
GROUND BEEF.
SALT AND PEPPER,
EQUAL RATIOS.
SOME CAYENNE.
SOME CUMIN--CAN'T BE
CHILI WITHOUT CUMIN.
NICE MEDLEY OF SPICES--
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER.
WE START SWEATING
THE VEGETABLES.
OIL IN THE PAN,
GREEN PEPPER.
THIS IS REALLY A SMALL AMOUNT
OF VEGGIES, COMPARATIVELY.
WE'RE MEAT EATERS.
RED PEPPERS.
AND THEN
OUR WHITE ONIONS.
GARLIC.
JALAPEÑOS.
SO LET THOSE SWEAT DOWN.
YEP. P.B.R.
OH, HO.
AND A PORTER.
AND A LITTLE PORTER.
COOKIN' WITH BEER--COULD BE
A WHOLE SHOW IN ITSELF.
SO WE DEGLAZE THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAN WITH THAT,
ALL THE GOODNESS
COMIN' OFF.
ALL THE FLAVOR.
NOW EVERYBODY'S GONNA
GET IN THE POOL?
YEP.
COOL. KIDNEY BEANS,
BLACK BEANS.
MM-HMM.
NICE MIX OF BEAN.
TOMATOES, AND THEN
HOT CHILI BEANS.
WHAT IS
A HOT CHILI BEAN?
BEANS AND CHILI PASTE.
SWEAT VEGETABLES.
STILL GOT SOME COLOR
AND SOME TEXTURE.
LOOKS OUTSTANDING.
AND THEN--
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
REALLY?
CHOCOLATE SAUCE.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
CHIPOTLES...
WITH ADOBO.
BROWN ADOBO.
WOW, THAT'LL BE
A NICE LITTLE KICKER.
THAT'S GOT SOME HEAT ON IT.
YEP.
SO HOW MUCH LONGER ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS SIMMER.
ABOUT 30 MINUTES OR SO.
AND WE LET IT SIT
USUALLY OVERNIGHT,
SO THAT ALL THE FLAVORS
CAN MELD.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TASTE THIS?
YEAH.
I MEAN, JUST FOR
TECHNICAL PURPOSES.
MMM. I'D EAT THAT
ALL DAY.
AND IT'S GOIN'
ON A 10-OUNCE BURGER
TO MAKE THE BLACK SABBATH.
SEASON--SALT AND PEPPER,
BLACKENING SPICE,
GARLIC POWDER, KOSHER SALT,
CHILI POWDER...
PAPRIKA, CAYENNE.
CAYENNE.
SO MARK IT BOTH SIDES AND THEN
YOU'LL HIT THE OTHER SIDE
WHEN YOU FLIP IT.
YEP. WE ADD OUR CHILI.
OKAY, WOW.
A LITTLE JALA-JACK.
PEPPERJACK CHEESE.
YEAH.
AND THEN IT GOES
IN THE SALLY TO MELT.
AND THIS IS A PRETZEL BUN?
ANYTHING'S GOOD ON THAT.
TOAST THE BUN.
ALL RIGHT, SO OUR BURGER...
(whistles)
TOP IT WITH SOME RED ONION
AND THERE YOU GO.
HO HO HO.
MM-HMM.
MMM.
OH.
THAT'S KILLER.
WELL-COOKED BURGER,
MEDIUM RARE,
GREAT CHILI ON IT,
A LITTLE SPICE.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
WHAT REALLY ENHANCES THIS
IS THAT PRETZEL ROLL.
MM-HMM.
THAT PRETZEL ROLL
IS LEGIT.
THAT'S A WHOLESOME,
ALL-AMERICAN GREAT BURGER.
THAT'S UP THERE IN THE TOP FIVE
BURGERS ON TRIPLE "D."
IT'S DELICIOUS. MAKES YOU
WANT TO KEEP EATING IT.
IT'S JUST A REALLY
ALL-AROUND GREAT BURGER
THAT YOU REALLY CAN'T FIND
ANYWHERE ELSE IN THE CITY.
THANKS.
WITH A CROWD TO MATCH.
YOU GET ALL KINDS
OF PEOPLE--
TATTOOS, NO TATTOOS,
BUSINESSMEN.
SHE'S A DERBY GIRL.
AS IN ROLLER DERBY?
YEP.
AS IN ROLLER DERBY.
MM-HMM.
I LIKE IT.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
I THREW PARTIES EVERY DAY.
NOW PEOPLE PAY
TO COME TO THE PARTY.
EXACTLY.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
THE FOOD
IS ALWAYS GOOD.
EVERY NIGHT YOU COME IN,
YOU GET SOMETHING NEW.
FROM PORK FRIES
WITH HOMEMADE BARBECUE SAUCE...
THANK YOU, BABY.
TO PICK-YOUR-OWN-INGREDIENTS
MAC AND CHEESE...
TOSSED A LITTLE CORN IN THERE,
SUN-DRIED TOMATOES
AND PROSCIUTTO--
IT WAS REALLY GOOD.
EVEN FRESH SEAFOOD.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS JUST FANTASTIC.
(woman)
MEDIUM-WELL METALLICA.
BUT IT'S THE BURGERS
THAT MAKE 'EM A LOCAL LEGEND.
I ALWAYS GET A BURGER.
EVERY TIME I'VE BEEN HERE
I'VE HAD A DIFFERENT ONE.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
THE LAIR OF THE MINOTAUR.
BRIE, POACHED PEARS
AND PANCETTA.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG
WITH THAT.
NOW WHEN I DROVE UP
AND I SAW
EVERYBODY CLAD IN BIG INK,
I DON'T THINK POACHED PEARS
WAS NECESSARILY GONNA BE
THE FIRST THING--
WE LIKE TO SHOCK
PEOPLE HERE.
I BET YOU DO.
WE'RE GONNA POACH
THE PEARS WITH GINGER ALE,
BOURBON.
WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
BOURBON, BOURBON,
WHISKEY, WHISKEY?
MM-HMM.
WHY DIDN'T YOU POUR IT
OUT OF THE BOTTLE?
WE HAVE IT ON TAP.
YOU HAVE BOURBON
ON THE BAR ON TAP.
I NEED YOU TO GET IN TOUCH
WITH ALL THE BOYS AT HOME.
WE'RE MOVING TO CHICAGO.
DON'T YOU CRY A LITTLE BIT
WHEN YOU POUR THAT?
(laughs)
CINNAMON STICKS,
A LITTLE BIT OF ANISE,
NUTMEG.
A LOT OF NUTMEG,
AND THEN SOME PEARS.
PEARS WE SOAK
IN GINGER ALE AS WELL.
SO THEY DIDN'T
TURN ON YOU?
YEP.
AND THEN YOU'RE JUST GONNA
POACH THESE LIGHTLY,
AND THEY'RE JUST GONNA
ABSORB ALL THAT.
YEAH.
WOW, THAT GOES
ON A BURGER?
IT TASTE AMAZING.
MM-HMM.
LET'S GET IT ON.
ALL RIGHT.
SALT AND PEPPER,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME CARAMELIZED ONIONS
ON THE FLAT TOP,
AND THEN WE HAVE OUR PANCETTA.
AHA.
PANCETTA--ITALIAN BACON,
SALT CURED.
IT SHOULD BE EATEN EVERY DAY.
PUT DOWN OUR ROLL.
THAT GETS FLIPPED.
GO AHEAD AND MOVE
OUR ONIONS.
OKAY.
OUR PANCETTA.
AND THEN WE COME IN
WITH OUR BRIE.
OH.
AND THEN WE'LL GO
IN THE SALAMANDER WITH THAT.
WE'LL TAKE OUT
THE POACHED PEAR NOW,
DO IT A MINUTE BEFORE
THE BURGER IS DONE.
THEN WE FAN THIS OUT.
THAT'S A LOT OF PEAR
FOR ONE BURGER.
BUT IT IS
A 10-OUNCE BURGER.
IT GOES
ON THE GRILL.
THE BRIE LOOKS LIKE IT'S
STARTING TO MELT OUT.
GOOD.
THEN WE TAKE OUR PEAR,
LAY IT ON TOP.
OH, THAT'S KILLER.
AND THERE YOU GO.
AND THIS IS THE...
LAIR OF THE MINOTAUR.
PERFECTLY COOKED.
MMM.
WOW. THAT'S LIKE GOING
TO "IT'S A SMALL WORLD"
IN THE DEATH BOAT.
MAN, I DON'T KNOW WHAT COUNTRIES
I JUST BLEW THROUGH.
A LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALTINESS,
GREAT PRETZEL ROLL AGAIN...
MM-HMM.
THE BRIE
AND THEN THIS POACHED PEAR
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BOURBON.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S DELICIOUS, MAN.
I WOULD NEVER THINK TO PUT
A PEAR ON A BURGER,
BUT IT'S EXCELLENT.
(man) ISN'T IT
CRAZY, THOUGH?
IT'S AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT,
A SLAYER BURGER.
INCREDIBLY UNIQUE.
TO HAVE A PLACE
WITH A BURGER
THAT'S THIS GOOD
AND WITH THE THEME OF METAL...
IT'S NOT PRETENTIOUS IN ANY WAY.
IT'S JUST FUN.
YOU'RE GONNA EAT ALL THIS
AND THEN GO DO...
YEAH.
ROLLER DERBY PRACTICE?
YOU GOTTA
WORK IT OFF.
HOW DO YOU THINK
WE STAY SO THIN?
I'M TELLIN' YA.
UP NEXT...
HERE YOU GO, RAY.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO ARIZONA...
IT'S JUST GREAT.
FOR SERIOUS COOKIN'...
THIS IS A FUN PLACE
TO HAVE GOOD FOOD.
AT A HOMETOWN JOINT.
WHOO!
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE NUMBER ONE
QUESTIONS WE GET ASKED
HERE ON TRIPLE "D"--
IS IT A DINER,
IS IT A DRIVE-IN,
OR IS IT A DIVE?
AND WE LIKE TO SAY, WELL,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT
NO MATTER WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE,
EVEN IF IT'S IN A STRIP MALL,
LIKE HERE IN FLAGSTAFF, ARIZONA,
AT BRANDY'S RESTAURANT
AND BAKERY.
WHOO! SHE'S
LOOKIN' GOOD.
IT'S JUST EXCELLENT FOOD.
BEEF STEW HERE.
FRESH IS THE BEST WAY
TO DESCRIBE IT.
LIME CHICKEN'S
BEING PLATED.
IT'S ALWAYS WONDERFUL.
GET WHAT YOU WANT
JUST HOW YOU WANT IT.
ENJOY.
WHAT DO PEOPLE LIKE
ABOUT THIS PLACE SO MUCH?
IT'S GOT
THE HOMETOWN FEEL.
THANKS TO HOMETOWN OWNERS
BRANDY WOJCIACK...
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
AND HER HUSBAND ED...
CALIFORNIA BURGER.
WHO OPENED THE PLACE
AS A BREAKFAST AND LUNCH JOINT
15 YEARS AGO.
EVERYBODY KNOWS YOU.
YOU'RE SUPER POPULAR.
AND THEN FIVE YEARS AGO
YOU GET THIS WILD IDEA
THAT YOU'RE GONNA
START DOING DINNER.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
SHERM DIGGITY SHOWED UP.
"SHERM DIGGITY"?
WHOO!
THAT'D BE
SHERMAN JOHNSON...
HERE YOU GO, RAY.
A WELL-TRAVELED CHEF
THEY'VE KNOWN FOR YEARS.
SALMON'S ON.
(Brandy) HE TRAVELED ALL OVER
THE WORLD--COSTA RICA...
SAUCE IS WORKING GOOD.
DECIDED TO COME
BACK TO THIS AREA.
THEN WE DECIDED--
LET'S DO DINNER.
OKAY, RISOTTO.
AND HE'S DOIN' IT
HIS WAY,
LIKE BEEF STEW MADE
ONE ORDER AT A TIME...
IT HAS KIND OF A SOUTHWESTERN
FLAIR. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
ANCHO HONEY CHICKEN WITH
CHIPOTLE RASPBERRY SYRUP...
MMM.
AND THIS ONE--A FLATIRON STEAK
DONE ARGENTINEAN STYLE.
THE CHIMICHURRI?
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA THROW A LITTLE BIT
OF A MARINADE ON.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
ANCHO CHILI POWDER IN THE BOWL.
LOT OF CHILIES UP HERE.
OH, YEAH.
NEW MEXICO CHILI POWDER,
BALSAMIC VINEGAR,
SOY OIL.
AND WHY SOY OIL?
IF YOU USE
A GOOD OLIVE OIL,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
TASTE IT ANYWAY.
RIGHT.
THEN I MIX SOME HONEY IN.
PRETTY THICK PASTE.
OH, YEAH, THIS IS A GOOD RUB.
WHEN THAT SETS UP...
THAT'S GREAT.
AND ALL THE FLAVORS MELD
TOGETHER, THEN I SCORE MY MEAT.
SCORING IT KEEPS IT
FROM TIGHTENING UP.
THEY GET SO CONFUSED.
THIS JUST RELAXES IT. YOU KNOW?
YOU'RE CONFUSING ME.
WELL, I CONFUSE THE HECK
OUT OF THIS MEAT.
DROP A NICE DOLLOP IN THERE,
AND THEN JUST RUB IT ALL AROUND
TO MAKE SURE
IT'S COATED REALLY GOOD.
AND I PUT IT
IN THE FREEZER.
OH, GOSH, HELP ME--
FREEZING MEAT.
FREEZING HELPS PUSH THAT
MARINADE DEEPER INTO THE MEAT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE
EVER HEARD THAT CONCEPT.
WELL, LEARN SOMETHING NEW
EVERY DAY.
AND IT'LL HELP TENDERIZE
YOUR MEAT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE CHIMICHURRI.
I MAKE CHIMICHURRI, TOO.
I'M A BIG FAN.
SO, UH, LET'S--
I LEARNED THIS
IN COSTA RICA.
GOOD PLACE TO LEARN IT.
YES, IT WAS.
OKAY.
DICED ONIONS, GARLIC,
DICED JALAPEÑO,
BLACK PEPPER, CRUSHED CHILIES,
KOSHER SALT.
THAT'S A LOT OF FLAVOR
RIGHT THERE IN ITSELF.
AS IT'S PROCESSING,
POUR IN A SEASONED RICE VINEGAR
AND LIME MIX.
OKAY, NOW I GOT A CANOLA
AND OLIVE OIL BLEND.
JUST ADD PARSLEY
AND CILANTRO.
THIS SETS OVERNIGHT
AND REALLY BLOSSOMS.
BREAK THAT PARSLEY
DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
YEP. PUT THAT
SCORED SIDE DOWN.
AND THAT LITTLE BAD BOY
WILL NOT TIGHTEN UP NOW.
AND WHAT I'M GONNA
DO FOR YOU,
SO WE CAN GET
EVERYTHING ELSE STARTED,
I'M GONNA BRING IT OVER HERE
AND SET IT RIGHT UP FRONT HERE
ON THE GRILL.
AND OVER HERE WE HAVE
THE SWEET POTATO...
SWEET POTATO CORN CAKE
WITH CHIPOTLE IN IT.
CORN CAKE GOING. OKAY.
THEN I'LL THROW
A NICE BIG HANDFUL
OF THESE DICED TOMATOES IN.
WE'LL MAKE THE PAN SAUCE NOW.
BEAUTIFUL CHIMICHURRI.
NICE HEALTHFUL PORTION.
KOSHER SALT,
ADD MY STOCK.
(whistles)
I'M LETTIN' IT REDUCE
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FLIP THIS CAKE--
NICE CARAMELIZED COLOR ON TOP.
PUT THE SPINACH IN THE BOWL.
PUT THE SWEET POTATO CORN CAKE
ON THERE.
IT SHOULD BE JUST FINE.
I'M GONNA SLICE
THIS BEAUTIFUL PIECE OF MEAT,
PLOP THIS RIGHT UP HERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
POUR THIS SAUCE ON.
LOOK AT THAT.
KNOCK YOURSELF OUT.
MMM.
WOW. THAT IS
REALLY GOOD.
YOU'VE GOT THE REALLY NICE,
TENDER MEAT,
BUT IT DOES HAVE
SOME BITE TO IT.
TRY IT WITH THAT
SWEET POTATO CORN CAKE.
MMM. THE CREAMINESS
OF THE SWEET POTATO CORN CAKE
BUT A LITTLE BIT OF SHARPNESS
FROM THE CHIMICHURRI...
MM-MMM GOOD, HUH?
NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
DYNAMITE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S JUST COOKED PERFECT.
IT'S AWESOME. IT'S TENDER,
GREAT SPICES.
GOOD?
EXCELLENT. EVERYTHING'S
BEEN GOOD...
IT'S JUST GREAT.
GOOD ATMOSPHERE,
NICE PEOPLE.
(chuckles)
LIKE A BIG FAMILY
IN HERE.
AWESOME.
JUST THE WAY
BRANDY AND ED WANT IT.
YOU GUYS DOING OKAY
OVER HERE?
IT'S A SMALL TOWN,
AND THESE PEOPLE COME IN,
AND THEY FEEL COMFORTABLE.
(Guy) HOW LONG
YOU BEEN COMIN' HERE?
OH, YEARS.
A COUPLE DAYS A WEEK,
EVERY WEEK.
EVERY WEEK, FOR YEARS.
YEP.
(man)
TEQUILA LIME CHICKEN.
IT'S NOT THE USUAL FARE.
YA THINK?
LIKE CURRIED FISH CAKES,
SAGE AND ROASTED GARLIC
STUFFED PORK CHOPS.
AND THE BEEF STEW--HE'S MAKIN'
THAT IN A SAUTé PAN.
THIS IS THE BISTRO BEEF STEW,
AND I MAKE THIS TO ORDER.
MADE TO ORDER AND STEW
DON'T GO TOGETHER.
THEY'RE A LITTLE STRANGE,
BUT IT WORKS.
SOMEWHERE THERE'S
A VILLAGE
THAT LOST THEIR GUY
FROM ANOTHER PLANET...
YEAH, THEY DID.
AND THEY WANT IT BACK.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA POP
THIS MEXICAN OREGANO IN,
BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC, CORIANDER,
OLIVE OIL, AND MAKE THIS
REAL NICE, SEE?
AND WE'RE GONNA GO
FOR THAT BISTRO BEEF TENDER.
THAT'S AN INTERESTING CUT.
COMPANIES JUST STARTED
COMING OUT WITH THIS
A COUPLE YEARS AGO. IT'S
A REALLY NICE CUT OF MEAT.
CUT 'EM INTO 1-OUNCE PORTIONS.
POUND 'EM BY HAND.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW TENDER--
IT REALLY GOES
GOOD IN THAT STEW.
JUST A QUICK POUND.
YOU KEEP SAYING STEW.
I MEAN...
IT IS A STEW.
IS IT REALLY
GOING TO STEW?
NO, IT'S NOT STEW.
OKAY.
IT'S IN HEAVY GRAVY. I DON'T
LIKE ANYTHING SITTIN' IN POTS.
NOT EVEN PLANTS?
HMM, SOMETIMES.
NOW THE MARINADE
ONTO THAT.
COAT IT NICELY.
I'M GONNA WRAP IT,
PUT IT IN THE FREEZER.
YOU'RE A FREEZER BELIEVER.
YEAH, I AM.
PULL IT OUT, THAW IT OUT--
THE STEW IS NOT GONNA
STEW FOR LONG.
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THIS.
SAUTé IT IN OLIVE OIL.
I'M JUST GONNA BROWN ONE SIDE.
I'M GONNA FLIP IT HERE.
NOW I'M PUTTING ON
A ROAST GARLIC POTATO CAKE.
OH.
AND I'M GONNA ADD TOMATOES,
OVEN-ROASTED VEGETABLES.
LOOK AT THAT BOUNTY
IN THE COUNTY.
A NICE LADLE
OF TOMATILLO PURéE...
I LOVE TOMATILLOS.
A NEW MEXICO CHILI SAUCE
I MAKE,
AND MY SOUR CREAM,
PAPRIKA AND BEEF STOCK.
WOW, THAT'S CRAZY. I LOVE
THE PAPRIKA COMIN' THROUGH.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN STOCK.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
A LITTLE FRESH SPINACH.
WE'RE GONNA PLATE
THIS GARLIC POTATO CAKE.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS STACK THE MEAT.
OH.
THEN WE JUST SMOTHER IT.
MMM. WOW.
I'M NOT TOO OVERWHELMED
BY STEWS ANYMORE,
BUT I WILL
TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
MAD SCIENTIST...
(laughs)
WHATEVER PLANET YOU'RE FROM,
DUDE, IT IS A CORNUCOPIA
OF FLAVORS--
SUPER-GREAT
FRESH VEGETABLE FLAVOR.
THE POTATO CAKE IS JUST LIKE
THIS NICE LITTLE GEM
RIGHT UNDERNEATH THAT. YOU
SHOULD BE THE CULINARY MAYOR.
I'M OUT. VERY GOOD.
I GOTTA GO.
(laughs)
BEAUTIFUL.
IT HAS GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S ALWAYS TENDER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD. IT'S NOT LIKE
AN OLD-FASHIONED BEEF STEW.
IT'S MODERN.
GREAT TASTING FOOD.
YUMMY.
THE FOOD IS DIFFERENT
FROM OTHER PLACES.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A FUN PLACE
TO HAVE GOOD FOOD.
COOL.
"THE SHERMANATOR"...
(vocalizes)
DO YOU PAY HIM?
OR DOES HE JUST LIVE HERE?
NO. HE'S JUST HERE
FOR FUN.
I LOVE FLAMES.
THAT'S FUNNY YOU SAY THAT,
BECAUSE THAT'S THE IMPRESSION
YOU GET FROM HIM.
(laughs)
YOU GOT IT GOIN' HERE. NICE
TO MEET Y'ALL. CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
WONDERFUL PLACE YOU HAVE.
NEXT STOP, SAN DIEGO...
I GOT TWO SWORD TACOS.
BEST FISH
YOU CAN GET IN TOWN.
WHERE A COUPLE OF FISHERMEN
ARE GRILLIN' UP...
MMM.
WHATEVER'S FRESH.
♪♪
WHEN I OPENED MY
FIRST RESTAURANT JOHNNY GARLIC'S
WITH MY BUSINESS PARTNER STEVE,
WE DID IT
ON A SHOESTRING BUDGET.
SO I'M DOWN HERE IN SAN DIEGO,
AND I HEAR
THERE'S A COUPLE BROTHERS
THAT HAVE DONE THE SAME THING.
NOW THESE GUYS
GOT THE CRAZY IDEA
OF OPENING A SEAFOOD RESTAURANT
IN A TOWN THAT'S FULL OF 'EM.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT? I HEAR
THESE GUYS ARE ROCKIN' IT.
BEST FISH YOU CAN GET IN TOWN.
THE FISH TACO
IS DELICIOUS.
BEST FISH SANDWICHES
IN SAN DIEGO.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD
AND FRESH ALL THE TIME.
AHI, SALMON, HALIBUT, SEA BASS.
GUYS--THEY KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
THAT'S 'CAUSE JUDD BRAUN...
LIKE ANYTHING ELSE?
AND HIS BROTHER MATT...
A TOMBO SANDWICH.
WERE CATCHING 'EM
WAY BEFORE THEY WERE
COOKING 'EM.
I'VE BEEN DOING FISHING
MY WHOLE LIFE
AND KNOW MY WAY
AROUND FISH.
STARTED OUT AT A FISH MARKET,
BASICALLY BEHIND THE COUNTER
CUTTIN' FISH.
YOU WERE OUT
ON THE FISHING BOATS?
YEAH, WORKING ON SPORT BOATS--
STARTED OUT AS A DECKHAND,
AND THEN ENDED UP
BEING THE COOK.
I GOT TWO SWORD TACOS.
NOW THEY'RE DOING IT
THEIR WAY IN THEIR PLACE.
ANYTHING ELSE FOR YOU?
AND THAT'S TO GO?
I DON'T SERVE
ANY FROZEN FISH.
WE DON'T
PRE-MARINATE ANYTHING.
'CAUSE YOU COULD LOSE
YOUR FLAVOR OF YOUR FISH.
EXACTLY.
AND THEY'RE EXACT ABOUT
THE BEST WAY TO COOK IT, TOO.
WE DO EVERYTHING
ON THE GRILL.
THE FISH
JUST FLAKES OFF.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
MMM.
TO ME, THE SIMPLER,
THE BETTER.
YOU REALLY CAN'T
BEAT IT.
(woman) SINGLE TACO.
(man) TACO SALAD PLATE
SANDWICH.
THERE YOU GO.
FROM LOCAL YELLOWTAIL
AND PACIFIC SWORDFISH...
SWORD LOOKS
REALLY NICE.
TO MAHI-MAHI AND HALIBUT.
THE HALIBUT SANDWICH
IS VERY FRESH.
HOW FRESH?
YOU'RE BREAKIN'
YOUR FISH DOWN 100%--
YOU'RE 100%-ING YOUR FISH.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S THE HARD WAY
OF DOING THINGS,
BUT IT'S GUARANTEED QUALITY
EVERY TIME.
IT'S THE BEST WAY
TO DO IT.
NOW HOW MUCH DOES
THIS MONSTER WEIGH?
THIS IS ABOUT
A 40-POUND FISH.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN,
BROTHER.
COME STRAIGHT DOWN
RIGHT ALONG THAT SPINE.
COME RIGHT BACK
UP THE TAIL.
YOU EVEN HAVE YOUR EYES OPEN
IN THE MIDDLE OF ALL THIS?
DONE IT
ONE OR TWO TIMES.
HOW MANY HALIBUT DO YOU THINK
YOU'VE BROKEN DOWN?
I'VE GOTTA SAY
IN THE THOUSANDS.
SO I'M GONNA COME BACK THROUGH
ONE MORE TIME.
YOU'RE RUNNIN' RIGHT ON TOP
OF THOSE BONES.
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT PERFECTLY
CUT HALIBUT FILLET LOIN.
WOW.
YOU KNOW THIS IS A REAL NICE
PIECE OF FISH
BECAUSE IT'S OPAQUE.
AND THEN YOU SKIN IT
AND THEN CUT IT DOWN.
THAT'S IT.
AND THEN IT GOES
BACK TO YOUR BROTHER,
AND THEN HE COOKS IT.
THEY GRILL IT UP
JUST PERFECT.
WITH YOUR CHOICE
OF HOMEMADE MARINADES.
CHIPOTLE.
TERIYAKI.
TERIYAKI. AND THEN YOU
GOT LEMON BUTTER
AND LEMON, GARLIC
AND BUTTER.
SO HOW WOULD YOU
RECOMMEND THIS HALIBUT
IF I WANT TO HAVE
A SANDWICH?
I WOULD DO A LEMON,
GARLIC AND BUTTER.
AND FOR THE SALAD?
LET'S DO THAT PIECE
WITH TERIYAKI.
SO THE FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA
DO IS ROLL IT IN BREADCRUMBS.
EVEN THOUGH IT
GOES ON THE GRILL?
YEP. WHEN YOU'RE DEALING
WITH A DELICATE WHITEFISH,
IT KINDA JUST WORKS
AS A BINDER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THE MARINADE
ON THE FIRST SIDE OF THE FISH.
LEMON, GARLIC AND BUTTER--
A LITTLE BIT OF FAT,
A LITTLE BIT OF FLAVOR.
LOOK AT THAT.
TERIYAKI.
OH, YOU CAN SMELL THAT GINGER
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
FRESH ROLL
FROM THE BREAD GUY.
THROW A LITTLE MARK
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
AND I'M GONNA BASTE IT AGAIN
WITH TERIYAKI.
AND WE HAVE OUR LEMON,
GARLIC AND BUTTER.
FRESH LEMON
ON TOP OF THAT.
SO THE FISH IS DONE.
THE BREAD--
LIGHTLY TOASTED.
TARTAR SPREAD, LETTUCE,
TOMATOES,
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION
ON THERE.
JUST DO A SMALL SALAD,
TOMATOES, ONIONS,
THROW SOME CUCUMBERS
ON THERE, CAPERS.
CAPERS?
VERY SEAFOODY-LIKE OF YOU.
TOP OF THE SALAD,
FRESH AVOCADO.
NICE.
SAME DEAL ON THE SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THESE THINGS.
THAT'S A MONSTER.
MMM.
THAT'S DELICIOUS. THERE'S
SOMETHING GOIN' ON HERE.
THE ROLL'S GOT
A NICE TOAST.
THE TARTAR SAUCE COMPLEMENTS
REALLY NICE. MMM.
SANDWICH IS DYNO, MAN.
WHAT A NICE SALAD. MMM.
SO MUCH FLAVOR FROM THAT FISH,
JUST A LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED
A DRESSING. MMM.
TERIYAKI'S ON POINT.
IT'S LIKE BUTTER.
I CHALLENGE ANYBODY THAT SAYS
THEY DON'T LIKE FISH--
TRY THAT AND TELL ME
THAT WOULDN'T MAKE THEM A FAN.
THAT HAPPEN--
THAT HAPPENS A LOT.
THEIR MOTTO IS "ALL WE DO IS
FISH," AND THAT'S ALL THEY DO.
THAT'S THEIR BUSINESS.
SERIOUSLY, NO BURGERS?
NO NOTHIN'. NO STEAKS.
NO HOT DOGS.
ALL WE DO IS FISH.
THE SEAFOOD'S AMAZING.
THAT'S WHY I COME HERE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOUR BASS TACOS TO GO.
I HAVE WHAT'S LEFT
OF A SWORDFISH TACO. MMM.
WE DO WHATEVER KIND
OF FISH TACO YOU WANT.
IT GETS LOADED UP
WITH FISH.
SO IF I WAS GONNA GO
FOR A FISH FROM THE CASE
FOR A TACO,
WHAT WOULD YOU RECOMMEND.
LET'S DO A SEA BASS TACO.
GET YOUR CHIPOTLE MARINADE.
IT'S CHIPOTLE PEPPERS, GARLIC,
BUTTER AND OREGANO.
IT GIVES IT A GOOD KICK.
WE DON'T TOP IT WITH SALSA.
YOU JUST DO IT--
EXACTLY.
HOW FAST WILL THIS GO,
ABOUT TWO MINUTES?
ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
GIVE IT ANOTHER LITTLE KISS
WITH THE SAUCE.
THE TORTILLA GOES ON.
LET THE CHEESE MELT.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA THROW THIS
RIGHT ON HERE NOW.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
GIVE IT A QUICK CHECK.
LOOKS GOOD.
WELL, THAT'S JUST TENDER
AND FLAKY--COMES RIGHT APART.
WE'VE ALMOST BLANKETED
THE WHOLE TORTILLA
WITH THE FISH.
YOU THINK I'M GONNA BE ABLE
TO CLOSE THAT THING UP?
OH, YEAH.
OH.
YEAH, YOU'LL EAT
THE REST WITH A FORK.
OH, THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT
YOU WERE GOING TO TELL ME.
JUST LIKE THAT.
NOW WE GOT OUR CABBAGE,
GREEN ONIONS,
RED ONIONS, TOMATOES,
TACO SAUCE.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
THAT FISH IS SO NICE
AND LIGHT AND FLAKY.
CHIPOTLE'S GOT SOME
NICE HEAT TO IT. MMM.
BUT YOU KNOW
WHAT THE KICKER IS?
THE MELTED CHEESE
ON THE TORTILLA.
THAT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE
FISH TACOS I'VE EVER HAD.
COLLEGE BY THE SEA.
YOU GOT A PhD
AT THE COLLEGE BY THE SEA,
DR. FISH TACO.
ALL RIGHT,
SINGLE MAHI TACO.
VERY TENDER,
VERY FLAKY.
I'VE JUST NEVER HAD
A TACO LIKE THAT BEFORE
UNTIL I CAME HERE.
'CAUSE, HEY,
IT IS DONE THEIR WAY,
JUST LIKE THIS
CALIFORNIA CLASSIC...
IT'S DEFINITELY NOT
YOUR STANDARD CIOPPINO.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
AT BLUE WATER SEAFOOD
IN SAN DIEGO...
FISH AND CHIPS
GRILLED.
BROTHERS JUDD AND MATT BRAUN
ONLY KNEW ONE THING...
IT'S WRITTEN RIGHT UP
ON THE BOARD UP THERE.
ALL THEY DO IS FISH.
HERE I COME.
IT'S AMAZING,
IT'S FRESH.
YELLOWTAIL, HALIBUT,
SOCKEYE SALMON.
AND THEIR OWN TAKE
ON A WEST COAST CLASSIC.
THIS IS CIOPPINO.
SO YOU'D EXPECT TO SEE
ALL KINDS OF SHELLFISH.
CRAB CIOPPINO'S USUALLY
LIKE MY BIG KICKER.
BUT NOT AT THIS JOINT.
DEFINITELY NOT
YOUR STANDARD CIOPPINO.
THIS IS THE WAY
WE DO IT.
'CAUSE MATT AND HIS BROTHER
ARE DEEP-SEA FISHIN' DUDES.
THEN WE'RE USIN' WAHOO,
MAHIMAHI,
AHI TUNA, SCALLOPS.
WE TRY TO USE SOMETHING
THAT'S STRONG IN FLAVOR...
AND GOOD TEXTURE.
SHOULD WE GET IT
GOIN' HERE?
YEP. TOMATO...
ALL THE VEGGIES FIRST--
CARROTS, YELLOW ONIONS, CELERY.
EVERYTHING
COOKS DOWN IN THERE.
LEEKS, ZUCCHINI,
GREEN PEPPERS, ANAHEIMS.
ANAHEIM.
CLAM JUICE, GARLIC,
WORCESTERSHIRE...
(whistles)
BLACK PEPPER.
SO IT'S REALLY
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL
UNTIL THIS BREAKS DOWN?
YEAH, 10 TO 15 MINUTES
LET THIS COOK.
SO THE TOMATOES AND THE VEGGIES
AND EVERYBODY'S COOKED DOWN.
NOW YOU PUT
THE FISH IN?
LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
TWO TO THREE MINUTES
WITH THE FISH,
SMELLS GREAT.
GOTTA LOVE CIOPPINO.
I'M TELLIN' YA,
MAN, I'M A CIOPPINO--
I'M A CIOPPINO,
UH, VINO.
CAN YOU BEAT A CIOPPINO VINO?
LOOK AT THAT.
WE CAN DO IT
OVER RICE
COOKED WITH CILANTRO,
PARSLEY, SALTED BUTTER.
THIS IS THE WAY
I PREFER IT.
THAT'S KINDA
HOW I ROLL. DUDE.
PLATTER FOR TEN.
I THINK YOU
CAN DEAL WITH IT.
MMM. OH, MAN.
LIKE IT?
THE FISH IS REALLY
NICE AND TENDER.
MMM. GOOD VEGGIE MIX
IN THERE.
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR
FROM THE LEEKS.
I'M PICKING UP SOME HEAT.
SERIOUSLY, I CAN'T STOP
EATING IT. THIS IS DYNAMITE.
IT HAS A NICE TOMATO BROTH,
DELICIOUS MEATY FISH.
VERY GOOD.
IT'S NOT ONLY SWEET, IT LEAVES
SOME HEAT. I LIKE THAT.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
ALL RIGHT, TYLER,
SINGLE TACO.
IS THIS PLACE LEGIT?
FOOD'S GREAT,
LEGIT PLACE.
THIS IS A GUY THAT IS MARRIED
TO A FANTASTIC CHEF.
CARISSA AND I WERE
IN THE FINAL THREE
FOR A SHOW CALLED
"THE NEXT FOOD NETWORK STAR."
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
HOW'S THE CIOPPINO?
FISH IS REALLY TENDER,
REALLY MOIST.
FRESH AND--
YEAH, VERY, VERY FRESH.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S FRESH, AND THAT'S
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
WHEN YOU'RE
EATING SEAFOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
THERE'S YOUR
SOCKEYE SAMMIE.
IT'S THE REASON I COME BACK
ALL THESE TIMES.
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN.
IT'S NEAT TO SEE THE TWO
BROTHERS ARE MAKING IT GO.
THANKS A LOT.
NICE TO MEET YOU, BROTHER.
ABSOLUTELY. GOOD STUFF, GUYS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YA
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IS IT WINNER, WINNER,
CHICKEN DINNER?
OR WINNER, WINNER, SEAFOOD,
SEA BASS TACO DINNER...
YEAH, THAT DIDN'T
GO THAT GOOD, DID IT?
OKAY, LET'S--LET'S NOT GO.
WE'LL FORGET WE DID THAT.
ALL RIGHT.