HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
(speaks nonsense)
GOULASH, EAT IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I KNEW IT.
MAMA'S COOKIN'
IN OKLAHOMA.
WELCOME TO MAMA E's.
SOUL FOOD.
WINGS AND WAFFLES...
PURE AWESOMENESS.
LIKE HIS MAMA MADE.
THIS IS GONNA BE
AN ADVENTURE.
AND A SOUL FOOD
FAVORITE...
GIVE ME A HIGH HOOF.
PIG'S FEET.
HIGH HOOF.
THE SAUCE IS OUTSTANDING.
THAT'S SOME FLAVORFUL
HOOF BROTH YOU'VE MADE.
IN DALLAS...
BRISKET GORDITAS.
BEST MEXICAN FOOD
IN DALLAS.
WHERE THIS GUY'S CRANKING OUT
THE FOOD HE GREW UP WITH...
YOU KNOW YOU'RE ALWAYS GONNA
GET GOOD FOOD, GOOD QUALITY
WHEN YOU WALK
IN THAT DOOR.
IN THE HOUSE
HE GREW UP IN.
IT'S READY.
THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE
SOUPS IN THE WORLD. MMM.
THIS IS MONEY POSOLE.
AND IN A LAS ANGELES
STRIP MALL...
(whistles) MIXED PIEROGI.
POLISH HOME COOKIN'.
SPECIAL PLACE.
WITH THREE KINDS
OF PIEROGI...
CAN WE CALL IT
THE TRIPLE "D" DELIGHT?
OKAY.
AND DESSERT
THAT'S ON FIRE.
MMM, I DIG THAT.
YOU WOULD LOVE THIS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO WHEN WE
WERE CRUISING TRIPLE "D"
THROUGH OKLAHOMA CITY,
WE HAD A CHANCE
TO EAT SOME KILLER BARBECUE
AT THIS PLACE CALLED LEO'S.
NOW BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
RIGHT ACROSS THE INTERSECTION
FROM LEO'S
IS ANOTHER GREAT PLACE
SERVING UP THREE GENERATIONS
OF SOUL FOOD.
IT'S TIME
TO CHECK OUT MAMA E's.
WELCOME TO MAMA E's.
WE HAVE NECK BONES,
CHICKEN AND DRESSING,
FRIED CATFISH
AND PIG'S FEET TODAY.
IT'S SOUL FOOD.
AM I SAYING IT WRONG?
IT'S SO'?
LEAVE THE "L" OFF.
SOUL FOOD.
IT TASTES LIKE SOMEBODY
PUT THEIR SOUL IN IT.
SOMEBODY LIKE
KEITH PATTERSON...
CATFISH UP.
WHO OPENED UP THIS JOINT ACROSS
THE STREET FROM HIS CHURCH
TWO AND A HALF YEARS AGO.
DO THEY CALL YOU KEITH
OR DO THEY CALL YOU PASTOR?
PASTOR.
EVEN WHEN
HE'S IN THE KITCHEN...
CATFISH IN.
COOKIN' UP
HIS MAMA'S RECIPE.
HER NAME WAS EVELYN.
AND THAT'S WHAT
YOU CALLED HER, MAMA E.
MAMA E. THIS WAS HER DREAM,
THOUGH, TO OWN A RESTAURANT.
YEAH, THIS WAS
HER DREAM.
REALLY?
YES.
AND A LOT OF HER RECIPES CAME
STRAIGHT FROM GRANDMA...
HE HAS SOME
OF BOTH OF US.
FROM DOWN-HOME CLASSICS...
THE DRESSING'S
SO JUICY.
SMOKED NECK BONES. MMM!
TO THIS JOINT'S
SIGNATURE DISH.
HERE'S YOUR WING
AND WAFFLE.
WINGS AND WAFFLES.
PURE AWESOMENESS.
THEY SPRINKLE THE CHICKEN
WITH POWDERED SUGAR?
IT'S A GOOD COMBINATION.
CHICKEN AND WAFFLES IS
THE FIRST THING WE'RE MAKING,
AND WE GOTTA
MARINATE THE CHICKEN.
YES, WE DO.
ADD THE BARBECUE SEASONING,
THEN THE SEASONING SALT,
GARLIC, BLACK PEPPER
AND THE CUMIN,
AGUA ONE AND TWO.
ADD THE WATER.
PUSH THAT ALL DOWN IN THERE.
HOW LONG THE WINGS
GONNA MARINATE?
THE WINGS--
45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR.
OKAY, SO THE WINGS
ARE MARINATING.
NOW WE MAKE
THE DREDGE.
WE'LL ADD THE CUMIN,
THE SEASONING SALT,
BARBECUE SPICE, GRANULATED
GARLIC, BLACK PEPPER.
DIG IT. INTO
THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR?
MIX ALL THAT UP. NOW WE'RE
READY TO BREAD THE WINGS.
JUST GONNA GIVE 'EM
A LITTLE--
A LITTLE DUSTIN'...
A LITTLE SHAKE.
DROP 'EM IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WHILE THAT'S FRYIN',
WE GO AND MAKE
THE WAFFLE BATTER.
RIGHT, YES.
OKAY, SO IT'S NOT
OUT OF A BAG, CORRECT?
NO, IT'S HOMEMADE.
I SHOULDN'T
EVEN HAVE ASKED...
OH, IT'S HOMEMADE.
HERE IN THIS KITCHEN. I JUST
TALKED IN THE MIDDLE OF CHURCH.
YEAH.
THIS IS CULINARY CHURCH
WITH PASTOR CHEF.
WE'RE GONNA BEAT TWO EGGS.
SUGAR, FLOUR, THE BUTTER.
VANILLA, THE CINNAMON...
CINNAMON.
BAKING POWDER.
AND THE SALT.
WHAT DO YOU
GOT OVER THERE?
AND THEN MILK IS GONNA
BRING ALL THAT TOGETHER.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT?
AND YOU'LL MAKE THIS IN
BIG OLD MONSTER BATCHES HERE?
OH, MAN, THIS MAKES
THE BEST WAFFLES.
THAT'S THICK LIKE SYRUP.
OH, YEAH.
AIN'T FOOLIN' AROUND WITH
THAT WAFFLE MAKER ARE YOU?
MNH-MNH.
LOAD' EM DOWN.
AND HOW LONG
DOES THIS ROLL?
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
(buzzer sounds)
OKAY, WHERE WE AT?
OHH, LOOK AT THAT.
READY?
PULL IT OUT.
WE'VE GOTTA DO ONE MAGICAL
THING WITH IT, YES.
WITH A BUCKET OF BUTTER?
MAKE IT REAL HEALTHY.
I'M LOSING THE ADDRESS
TO THIS JOINT.
GET THE WINGS.
NOW YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO PUT SYRUP ON.
OH, SYRUP
AND POWDERED SUGAR,
WE'LL JUST DRIZZLE
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT.
OHH.
OH, WAIT, WHERE'S THE HOT SAUCE.
YOU NEED SOME HOT SAUCE.
THE CRUST ON THAT CHICKEN'S
SO HARD--THIS THING--
WATCH THIS--I GOT IT. I GOT--
WHO WANTS A PIECE OF THIS?
IT MELTED THE FORK.
NOW TRY THAT.
OH, ARE YOU SURE?
YES.
THIS IS GONNA BE
AN ADVENTURE.
MMM.
IT'S GOOD STUFF,
ISN'T IT?
THAT'S CRAZY. SO WHERE DO YOU
THINK CHICKEN WAFFLES CAME FROM?
ALL I KNOW
IS WE USED TO EAT IT...
AS A KID.
SO YOU'RE GETTING THE CRUNCHY
SALTINESS OF THE WINGS
WITH THE SWEET CRUNCHINESS
OF THE WAFFLE,
POWDERED SUGAR,
MAPLE SYRUP,
A LOT OF BUTTER
AND HOT SAUCE.
YOU'RE GONNA SEE THAT
EVERY DAY, RIGHT?
MMM. AMEN.
IT TASTES LIKE
FRIED CHICKEN,
BUT YOU CAN KINDA TASTE
THE SUGAR IN IT.
WING WAFFLE UP.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANY CHICKEN
ANY BETTER THAN THIS.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S GONNA BE
A WAFFLE KINDA DAY.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
FOR IT FOR YEARS.
THE FOOD
IS REALLY GREAT.
CATFISH IS UP.
(woman) THANK YOU.
JUST EXACTLY WHAT YOU WANT
AND A LITTLE AMPLIFIED.
A LITTLE?
TWO BIG PORTIONS
OF MEAT.
FROM FRIED CHICKEN
AND RIBS...
OUGHTA BE ILLEGAL 'CAUSE
THEY'RE REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
TO CATFISH AND NECK BONES.
BLACK-EYED PEAS...
WITH YOUR CHOICE
OF THREE SIDES.
AND WHAT'S
YOUR TWO OTHER SIDES?
THE OKRA
AND THE MASHED POTATOES.
JUMPIN' ON
SOME MORE YAMS.
COLLARD GREENS.
LOAD UP
ON THE GREENS!
AND THE COMPLIMENTARY
KOOL-AID.
I MEAN, THAT'S
A FAMILY REUNION RIGHT THERE.
WHEN I THINK OF MAMA E's,
I THINK OF MY
GRANDMOTHER'S COOKIN'.
MY GRANDMOTHER
USED TO COOK PIG'S FEET.
HIS, TOO.
AIN'T NOTHING WRONG
WITH NO PIG FEET, PARTNER.
WE GET AFTER
SOME PIG FEET, DO YA?
IT'S PIG FEET.
IT'S REAL SOUL FOOD.
DELICIOUS.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE EVER
GOT DOWN WITH THE HOOF.
THE HOOF IS THE BEST.
GIVE ME A HIGH HOOF.
HIGH HOOF.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, YEAH, NOW.
SO ANYHOW, WATER FIRST.
THE CHICKEN BASE,
ONIONS, BELL PEPPERS...
A LITTLE BASIL.
BASIL, CHOPPED GARLIC,
CRACKED RED PEPPERS.
OH, I LIKE THIS.
MAMA E's SECRET BLEND.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
TELL ME WHAT THAT IS?
I CAN'T TELL YOU
WHAT THAT IS.
HANG ON A SECOND.
HANG ON.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
LET ME ASK IF YOU
IF THIS IS WHAT IT IS.
MM-HMM.
HIGH HOOF!
SEASONING SALT
WE JUST PUT IN.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
ADDING THE VINEGAR
TO THIS.
VINEGAR'S GONNA TAKE
SOME OF THAT SWINE-Y OUT.
OH, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
I SAID SWINE-Y.
OKAY.
THEN WE ADD A LITTLE
BIT MORE WATER THERE.
NOW WE'RE DONE.
YOUR FOIL, SIR. WRAP IT UP.
LET ME GET THE OVEN.
OH, MY GOSH, WHAT IS THIS,
CENTER OF THE EARTH?
YES.
I'D WEIGH 95 POUNDS IF I WORKED
IN THIS KITCHEN. THIS IS HOT.
HOUR AND A HALF.
PULL 'EM OUT OF THE OVEN.
PULL THAT
OFF OF THERE.
MAKE SURE YOU GET ME
AN AL DENTE PIG FEET.
SO THAT LOOKS LIKE
A RATIO OF, LIKE, 50% FAT...
FAT.
50% MEAT.
THAT'S IT.
SO THAT'S LIKE AN EXTRA
20 MINUTES ON THE TREADMILL.
BUT I DON'T DO IT.
MMM, REALLY GOOD.
THE FLAVOR'S MONEY.
IT'S CHEWY,
BUT IT'S SUPER TENDER,
SO IT'S BEEN COOKED DOWN
THE RIGHT WAY.
MM.
BUT THEN THE FAT IS LIKE BUTTER.
IT IS MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE SAUCE IS OUTSTANDING.
THAT'S SOME FLAVORFUL
HOOF BROTH YOU'VE MADE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
IT'S SIMILAR TO BACON.
IT'S SALTED, CURED MEAT.
GARLIC AND PEPPER
AND HERBS.
IT'S JUST
A FAMILY TRADITION,
SOMETHING THAT WE'VE DONE
SINCE WE WERE KIDS.
YOU WANT CORNBREAD
OR A ROLL?
CORNBREAD.
BUT IT IS SOMETHING IN
REMEMBRANCE OF THE ANCESTORS.
IT'S FOOD THAT COMES
FROM THE HEART.
HEY, GRANDMA,
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
WHAT'S--IS HE
KNOCKING IT OUT?
OH, I'M SO PROUD.
MY HEART IS SO BIG.
YOU KNOW WHAT, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO START
HOLDING CHURCH AT LUNCH.
I'M VERY HAPPY
FOR YOU, MAN.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
LARGE POSOLE.
EVERYTHING'S HANDMADE.
YEAH.
A MEXICAN TAKE
ON SOUP AND A SANDWICH...
BRISKET GORDITAS
ALWAYS HITS THE MARK.
AND TAMALES MADE MOM'S WAY.
I'VE GONE TAMALE
GONE WILD RIGHT HERE, BUT--
NO, NO, NO,
THAT'S ACTUALLY GOOD.
MMM. IT IS SO DELICATE
AND TENDER.
AT MY HOUSE IN CALIFORNIA,
MY FRIENDS AND FAMILY
ARE ALWAYS COMING OVER TO EAT.
IF I DIDN'T ALREADY
OWN RESTAURANTS,
WELL, I PROBABLY SHOULD'VE
TURNED IT INTO ONE.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT THE AVILA FAMILY DID
WITH THEIR HOUSE HERE
NORTH OF DOWNTOWN DALLAS.
NOW IN TRIPLE "D" LANGUAGE,
WE'D CALL THIS A LOCAL FAVORITE.
BRISKET GORDITAS.
YES.
WELL, THIS IS THE SECOND
TIME THIS WEEK.
IT'S ONLY MONDAY.
I KNOW.
I NEED TWO TOSTADAS.
FOOD'S ALWAYS GOOD.
MADE BY HAND.
FROM TEX-MEX...
GREAT ENCHILADAS.
CHICKEN AND BEEF.
TO THE MEXICAN CLASSICS
RICARDO AVILA GREW UP ON.
WE'RE STICKING WITH
MY MOM AND DAD'S ROOTS,
VERY TRADITIONAL MEXICAN.
THE POSOLE SOUP.
BRISKET GORDITAS
ALWAYS HITS THE MARK.
THEN THIS FAVORITE...
THE TAMALES.
REALLY GOOD TAMALES.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A CHILI PURéE
THAT WE'RE GONNA USE
FOR THE MASA,
FLAVOR UP THE MASA.
I'VE MADE A LOT
OF TAMALES IN MY DAY,
BUT I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE
EVER FLAVORED MY MIXTURE.
GAUJILLO PEPPERS?
ACTUALLY,
THOSE ARE CASCABEL.
I WAS JUST
GONNA SAY THAT.
YEAH.
THESE HAVE BEEN RECONSTITUTED
IN SOME HOT WATER.
EXACTLY.
POUR IN A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT THERE, GARLIC...
CUMIN.
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT LIQUID
THAT WE STEEPED
THE PEPPERS IN.
YES.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE SOME NOISE.
HIT THE THROTTLE.
SURE. SURE.
WE CAN GO WITH THAT.
SCARED YOU A LITTLE BIT,
DIDN'T IT?
IT DID, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT. SO HOW DO YOU COOK
THE PORK BUTT FOR THE TAMALES?
PUT IT IN A STOCKPOT,
COVER IT,
ADD SOME ONIONS, GARLIC,
LITTLE BIT OF SALT, PEPPER.
COOK IT UNTIL
IT'S JUST TENDER.
WE PULL THE PORK FROM THE BONE.
IT GETS CHOPPED.
WE PUT IT IN A PAN
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF LARD,
A LITTLE BIT MORE GARLIC,
SALT WITH SPANISH PAPRIKA,
SOME CHILI POWDER,
PURéED CHILIES,
FRIES UP AND THAT'S WHAT GOES
IN THE PORK TAMALES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE MASA.
FIRST I'M GONNA
ADD THE CORN FLOUR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME GARLIC, COMINO OR CUMIN.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BAKING POWDER.
BAKING POWDER, SOME LARD,
AND NOW WE'VE GOT
SOME OF THE STOCK THAT
WE COOKED OUR PORK BUTTS IN.
HOW MANY LADLES?
PROBABLY ABOUT
ANOTHER FOUR.
WE ALSO STILL HAVE TO ADD IN
OUR CHILI SAUCE.
CORRECT.
YOU SAY CHUG.
HOW'S THAT?
YEAH, THAT'S GREAT.
ISN'T THAT A GREAT COLOR?
WE'RE JUST GETTING, YOU KNOW,
ALL THE GRITTINESS OUT OF IT.
GET THE HEEL
OF YOUR HAND IN THERE.
SO WE'RE
PRETTY MUCH THERE.
OKAY, SO IT'S TIME
TO DO TAMALES.
WE USE THIS HIGH-TECH DEVICE
TO SPREAD THE MASA.
OH, LOOK WHAT IT SAYS
RIGHT THERE--"PROPERTY OF NASA."
THE CORN HUSK,
WHICH IS DRIED,
THEN SOAKED IN WATER
IS WHAT WE USE AS THE BASIS.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE MASA, WE GO THAT HIGH,
AND THEN GO TO THE END.
HERE, I'LL LET YOU
GET IN THERE.
OH, THANKS.
AND EVEN SPREAD.
WE HAVE TO GET ENOUGH
TO THE END NOW.
SO NOW WE'RE GOING
WITH THE PORK.
OKAY.
YOU WANT TO GET
ENOUGH IN THERE,
BUT YOU DON'T WANT
TO GO TOO CRAZY.
I'VE GONE TAMALE GONE WILD
RIGHT HERE, BUT--
NO, NO, NO,
THAT'S ACTUALLY GOOD.
WE GO LEFT SIDE FIRST, AND THEN
BRING THAT OTHER SIDE OVER,
AND THEN JUST BRING
THAT TAIL FORWARD,
AND THEN
THERE YOU GO.
AND THEN ROLL IT UP.
IT'S EXACTLY HOW I MAKE 'EM.
AND THEN YOU JUST START
YOUR LITTLE STACKING PROCESS.
WE LOAD UP ALL THE TAMALES,
STEAM 'EM HOUR AND A HALF,
TWO HOURS.
YEP.
THIS COMES OFF...
YES.
AND NOW
WE GRAB THESE OUT?
YES, ONE OF THOSE,
OR A COUPLE OF THOSE.
DID YOU WANT ONE?
UH, SURE.
NO, WAIT.
THANK YOU.
MMM, IT IS SO DELICATE
AND TENDER.
THAT'S
A FANTASTIC TAMALE.
IT DOESN'T NEED ANYTHING
OTHER THAN HOT SAUCE.
I DON'T THINK
IT NEEDS HOT SAUCE. MMM.
I ALWAYS TELL PEOPLE
WHEN THEY ORDER TAMALES...
SHH, SHH, SHH, SHH. YOU TALK
IN THE MIDDLE OF EVERYTHING?
YEAH, USUALLY. YEAH.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE ALWAYS GONNA
GET GOOD FOOD, GOOD QUALITY
WHEN YOU
WALK IN THAT DOOR.
TORTILLA SOUP.
IF YOU CAN EVEN
FIND THE PLACE.
DRIVING DOWN MAPLE,
YOU WOULD PASS IT
AND NOT EVEN KNOW
WHAT IT IS.
AVILA SPECIAL.
OKAY.
I THOUGHT I WAS PULLING
INTO SOMEONE'S HOUSE.
YEAH, IT USED TO BE.
ALMOST LIKE BEING HOME.
'CAUSE RICARDO'S DOING IT ALL
THE SAME WAY HIS MOM DID...
LARGE POSOLE.
WHEN IT WAS HOME.
EVERYTHING'S HANDMADE.
YEAH.
FROM THE ENCHILADAS...
ALL THE INGREDIENTS
ARE REAL FRESH.
TO THE CHILI RELLENOS...
THEY GRILL IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND THIS MEXICAN SANDWICH
CALLED A GORDITA.
I DO NOT KNOW THAT I HAVE
EVER SEEN A GORDITA PRESS.
YEAH, WE'RE
TALKIN' HIGH TECH.
YOU TAKE THREE FINGERS TO GET IT
TO THE RIGHT SIZE. THERE YOU GO.
THE SECOND PART
IS THE HEEL OF THE HAND.
THEN WE GO DOWN
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
TECHNICAL PROCESS
I LEARNED FROM MY MOM AND DAD.
AND NOW A LITTLE BIT
OF PRESSURE.
YOU LOOK AT IT.
YOU GIVE IT ABOUT A 180.
AGAIN, A LITTLE BIT
OF PRESSURE.
YOU KNOW, IT MAKE TAKE,
YOU KNOW, TWO OR THREE,
YOU MAKE
ONE OF THESE A DAY?
PRETTY MUCH, YEAH.
OKAY, NOW I'M
GONNA TRY IT.
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
NO!
OH, OH,
OH, OH, OKAY.
WE ARE GOING--DUDE.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA DO ONE PRESS
AND A TWIST AND A PRESS.
OKAY, JUST
DON'T TELL MOM.
NOW I'M NOT SAYING
IT'S PERFECT.
OH, ACTUALLY,
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
CRISP IT UP,
THEN FILL IT WITH BRISKET.
LIKE THIS?
YEAH, AND HOWEVER MUCH
YOU WANT.
MMM, THE FLAVOR,
THE TEXTURE,
A LITTLE CRISP
ON THE OUTSIDE, MMM.
BRISKET GORDITAS
ARE INFAMOUS AROUND TOWN.
FOOD'S ALWAYS GOOD
EVERY TIME WE COME HERE.
BEST THING ON THE MENU,
HANDS DOWN, WHAT IS IT?
OH, I LIKE
THE POSOLE SOUP.
IT'S CHICKEN AND HOMINY
IN A CHILI SAUCE.
I'VE GOTTEN IT
EVERY TIME I COME.
SO NOW
IT'S POSOLE TIME.
WE'RE GONNA COOK UP A LITTLE
BIT OF THE PURéED CHILI.
THIS IS THE CASCABEL.
THE CASCABEL, SO THE SAME ONE
THAT WE USED FOR THE TAMALE.
RIGHT. SO WE'RE
ADDING A LITTLE OIL,
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS CHILI IN THERE, SALT,
GONNA ADD SOME GARLIC, AND THEN,
OF COURSE, REALLY WHAT MAKES
A POSOLE IS THE DRIED OREGANO,
MEXICAN OREGANO.
VERY LIGHT AMOUNT
OF SEASONING.
YES, YEAH. WE'LL
ADD SOME CHICKEN STOCK...
INTO THIS?
INTO THIS, YEAH.
OKAY. SO WHILE
THAT'S SIMMERING...
WE'RE GONNA GET
THE POSOLE GOING.
NOW WE'RE CALLING
THIS POSOLE, THE CORN?
FOR US, IT'S POSOLE, YOU KNOW
THAT KERNEL WITHOUT THE GERM.
SEE, I ALWAYS
GET IT WRONG.
I ALWAYS SAID,
"HEY, WATCH OUT, MAN,
WE'RE GETTING PULLED OVER
BY THE POSOLE."
(laughs)
SOME MORE
CHICKEN STOCK?
SOME MORE OF OUR STOCK
TO THAT POSOLE.
NOW YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK, RIGHT?
OH, YEAH.
YOU LEAVE THAT TO SIMMER?
YEAH, I THINK SO.
THAT LOOKS
LIKE MOUNT VESUVIUS.
ADD THAT TO THE POT.
LET THIS SIMMER.
THEN WE HAVE
OUR SHREDDED CHICKEN.
SO WE'LL LET THAT COME TO
A SIMMER, AND IT'LL BE READY?
20 MINUTES OR SO.
HOLY POSOLE.
IT'S READY.
THIS IS ONE OF MY
FAVORITE SOUPS IN THE WORLD.
AND THIS COMES
WITH EACH PLATE?
YEP.
LITTLE BIT
OF SAVOY CABBAGE, OREGANO
AND A LITTLE BIT OF LIME.
MMM. THIS IS
JUST OUTSTANDING.
THE POSOLE IS SO TENDER,
SITTING IN THAT BROTH. MMM.
WHEN YOU WANT TO THINK
ABOUT POSOLE, MAN,
THAT RIGHT THERE IS
A DICTIONARY DEFINITION.
THIS IS MONEY POSOLE.
(woman) AND, OF COURSE,
WITH THE LIME SQUEEZED IN
ON TOP OF IT, IT'S WONDERFUL.
THIS IS THE PLACE.
HANDS DOWN.
BRISKET GORDITAS.
BEST MEXICAN FOOD
IN DALLAS.
YOU GONNA
EAT ALL THAT?
I'M GONNA PROBABLY EAT
ALL THE POSOLE.
THEY HAVE A SHORTAGE
OF POSOLE HERE.
MAYBE YOU DON'T WANT
TO EAT IT ALL.
BROTHER MAN, SERIOUSLY,
YOU OWNED IT.
NEXT STOP,
AN L.A. STRIP MALL.
UNUSUAL.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
THE FAMOUS
POLISH PIEROGI.
POLISH COOKING.
MMM, THAT'S BETTER THAN ANY
PIEROGI I'VE EVER TRIED.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
SO HERE I AM IN LOS ANGELES,
AND YOU KNOW,
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY
THAT YOU CAN FIND ONE PLACE
TO GET ALL
OF YOUR NEEDS FULFILLED.
IT TAKES A REAL SPECIAL PLACE
LIKE HERE AT THE KEY CENTER,
'CAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW.
I MEAN, YOU'RE IN, YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR A DOUGHNUT MAYBE
WHILE YOU'RE GETTING
SOME WATER FILLED UP
OR YOU'RE AT THE MARKET
OR HITTING THE LAUNDROMAT OR
GETTING YOUR HAIR DONE OR MAYBE
YOU'RE AT THE WESTERN UNION
OR GETTING A VIDEO OR HITTING
SOME ALTERATIONS & CLEANING,
AND AFTER A DAY OF SHOPPING
LIKE THAT, WELL, YOU'RE HUNGRY,
AND, OF COURSE, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE SOME--YEP, POLISH FOOD.
LET'S CHECK OUT POLKA.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
YOUR GOURMET MEAL.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S LIKE COMING
TO MY FAVORITE COUSIN'S HOUSE.
PIEROGI ARE READY.
IT IS TRADITIONAL
POLISH FOOD.
I'M GONNA MISPRONOUNCE IT.
KRóLEWSKI, STUFFED CABBAGE.
IT'S SO UNUSUAL.
UNLESS YOU
GREW UP IN POLAND...
FRESH DILL.
LIKE KATHERINE DABROWSKI.
I ALWAYS HELPED MY GRANDMOTHER
AND MY MOTHER COOK.
NOW SHE'S COOKING
IN HER OWN PLACE...
VOILà.
WHERE SHE
AND HER HUSBAND ANDREW...
ALL RIGHT.
ARE CRANKING OUT
THE CLASSICS.
THE FAMOUS POLISH PIEROGI.
LIKE PIEROGI
SERVED THREE WAYS.
CHEESE AND POTATO PIEROGI.
SOME FILLED WITH SAUERKRAUT
AND SOME WITH MEAT.
WE ARE MAKING
PIEROGI DOUGH.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
YES. ONE EGG.
SO ADD SOME WATER.
CRANK IT UP.
WAY TO KINDA DROP
THE CLUTCH INTO FOURTH. CA-CAW!
SO HOW LONG
DO WE MIX THIS UP?
FOR ABOUT
FIVE TO SEVEN MINUTES.
SO WHY DON'T
WE JUST TAKE SIX?
OKAY, SIX MINUTES.
IF WE NEED TO DO
THE EXTRA MINUTE,
WE'LL GIVE IT TO YOU
FOR FREE.
OKAY, WONDERFUL.
SO THIS IS DONE.
DOESN'T SHE LOOK
LIKE SNOW WHITE?
AND WE'RE HERE IN
THE SNOW WHITE KITCHEN.
AND I'M THE EIGHTH DWARF.
I'M PIEROGI.
YES.
OKAY.
ALREADY WANTS ME
OUT OF HERE. OKAY.
THEN THE DOUGH IS GOING
TO REST FOR A MINUTE.
IT'S HAVING A TIME-OUT.
YOU STAY RIGHT THERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE FILLING.
WE MAKE POTATO
AND CHEESE.
BUT I CAN
TRY ALL THREE.
YEAH. WE WILL
START WITH POTATOES.
OKAY.
CREAM CHEESE.
IS IT A POLISH THING?
WE USE A LOT
OF WHITE CHEESE.
CREAM CHEESE I LIKE THE MOST
HERE IN AMERICA.
THIS IS VEGETA.
THE WHO-HEY?
VEGETA.
IT'S A DRIED VEGETABLE
SEASONING. DIG IT.
YES, WE USE IN POLAND A LOT.
BLACK PEPPER.
DOES POLISH FOOD
HAVE ANY SPICE?
YOU MEAN, LIKE, MEXICAN THEY
HAVE CHIPOTLE AND ALL THAT?
YEAH.
NO.
BUT YOU HAVE VODKA.
WE DO HAVE VODKA.
THAT MAKES UP FOR IT.
YEAH. THIS IS
CURRY POWDER.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
YOU USE CURRY POWDER?
I DO.
I LIKE CURRY POWDER.
IN POLISH FOOD?
I DO, TOO.
NOW WE WILL MIX
FORM FROM THAT,
LITTLE SMALL BALLS.
ROLL IT IN THE BALLS,
FORM THE DOUGH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
CUT THE DOUGH...
THE DOUGH, RIGHT.
OKAY, TWO OF THOSE
GO AROUND ONE?
JUST ONE.
THAT'S GONNA
STRETCH OUT AROUND THAT?
YES.
(whistles)
AND NOW YOU HAVE TO STRETCH
IT OUT LIKE A PIZZA.
OH, HERE YOU GO.
THAT'S THE WAY.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
TWO, THREE.
NICE!
OHH!
TAKE ONE IN THE MIDDLE KINDA
AND NOW FLIP IT
IN THE MIDDLE AND THEN
THE SIDES--LOOKS PERFECT.
I SHOW YOU A TRICK. TAKE
SOME FLOUR, JUST A LITTLE.
TAKE A LITTLE
MORE FLOUR.
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, AND TWIST
AND TWIST AND VOILà.
AND THEN WE GO OVER THERE,
AND WE BOIL 'EM?
THEN WE SAUTé THEM,
AND THEN WE WILL EAT THEM.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTé SOME ONIONS
IN A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
YES, SPICES.
THIS IS YOUR OWN BLEND?
YES.
A LITTLE SEASON SALT
WITH A KICK.
WE HAVE TWO
POTATO AND CHEESE,
ONE SAUERKRAUT AND MUSHROOMS,
AND ONE MEAT.
ALL OF THAT'S FOR ME?
YES.
ALL RIGHT. SALT THE WATER?
BIG GIGANTIC POLISH RAVIOLI.
HOW LONG DOES THIS TAKE?
APPROXIMATELY FIVE MINUTES.
GARLIC, LOTS OF GARLIC.
AND THIS IS HOW
THEY DO IT IN POLAND?
MAYBE NOT SO MUCH
GARLIC, BUT, YES.
I USE A LOT OF GARLIC
BECAUSE I LOVE GARLIC.
HOW LONG
DO THEY SIT IN THERE?
OH, ONE MINUTE.
MOUTH'S WATERING.
THIS ALL FIT ON HERE?
YES.
MMM, WOW. THAT'S BETTER THAN
ANY PIEROGI I'VE EVER TRIED.
OH, WHAT'S THIS
LITTLE GEM GONNA BE?
OH, WINNER, WINNER,
SAUERKRAUT AND MUSHROOMS.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
DELICIOUS.
THIS IS THE ONE
I'M LOOKING FOR--THREE MEAT.
MMM.
CAN I HAVE ALL THREE OF THEM
PUT TOGETHER FOR ONE?
I MEAN, CAN WE CALL IT
THE TRIPLE "D" DELIGHT?
OKAY.
OH, HEAVENLY.
PIEROGI AND GOULASH.
OH, I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE HAVING.
GOULASH.
OOH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WE ARE MAKING GOULASH.
IT LOOKS
LIKE FLANK STEAK.
YES. AND NOW I'M GOING TO CUT
THIS, MAKE SMALL DIAMONDS.
SMALL DIAMONDS.
YEAH. NOW WE WILL
MARINATE THIS MEAT.
OKAY.
VEGGIE OIL,
ONION, PAPRIKA...
YEAH.
CHICKEN BASE.
OKAY, SO...
BAY LEAVES.
GOT IT.
MM-HMM. BLACK PEPPER.
WILD WITH THE PEPPER.
CURRY POWDER, SOME VEGETA,
HAS TO BE GARLIC,
TOMATO SAUCE.
VERY VANNA WHITE-ISH
WITH THE HAND AND THE SWIRL.
IT'S MARJORAM.
REALLY? IS THAT BIG
IN POLISH FOOD?
YES, WE USE A LOT.
SO THIS IS GONNA MARINATE
FOR HOW LONG?
24 HOURS.
WE ARE
GOING TO BAKE THIS.
GOULASH BAKES?
YEAH, FOR ONE HOUR...
OKAY.
AND 45 MINUTES.
350 DEGREES.
ACTUALLY IT'S 500.
500 DEGREES?
YEAH, 500 DEGREES.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE WHAT'S
IN HERE. GIMME GOULASH.
NOW WE HAVE TO DO
THE STARCH INTO THE MIXTURE.
LOVE IT.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
STIR IT.
AND NONE OF IT BURNED.
THEN WHAT DO WE SERVE IT WITH?
POTATO DUMPLINGS.
AND IN THEY GO.
A LITTLE SALT WATER?
YES.
THAT'S THE SOME MIXTURE
THAT WE DO FOR THE PIEROGIES.
THE SAME MIXTURE.
PULL 'EM, YOU POP 'EM...
(speaks nonsense)
GOULASH AND EAT IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I KNEW IT.
OKAY.
HOW MANY
YOU GIVING ME?
WELL, YOU LIKE TO EAT,
RIGHT?
(Guy) NICE AND TENDER. MMM.
A REALLY CREAMY,
TENDER GNOCCHI.
MMM, WOW. THE FLANK STEAK'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITE CUTS OF MEAT,
BUT I'VE NEVER HAD IT
COOKED DOWN LIKE THAT.
IT FALLS APART
LIKE BRISKET.
OHH, MAN,
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
FABULOUS.
REALLY EXCELLENT.
NEVER HAD
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
I WILL DEFINITELY
COME BACK FOR THAT.
AND SPEAKING OF COMING BACK,
WHEN YOU COME BACK,
YOU'RE GONNA SEE A DESSERT
THAT'S ON FIRE... LITERALLY.
ANDREW, KIELBASA.
AT POLKA
IN AN L .A. STRIP MALL...
AWESOME LITTLE
POLISH RESTAURANT.
BIGOS IS READY,
TOO. NEXT.
KATHERINE DABROWSKI...
GREAT MEALS
FOR GREAT GUESTS.
AND HER HUSBAND ANDREW...
AND THE ROYAL PLATTER
FOR THE KING.
ARE TURNING OUT
THEIR CHILDHOOD FAVORITES.
MIXED PIEROGI.
STUFFED CABBAGE
AND ALSO THE GOULASH--
EXCELLENT AS ALWAYS.
AND TO TOP IT OFF...
MADAM, BON APPéTIT.
NALESNIKI, WHICH IS
A ROLLED CREPE--OH, WONDERFUL.
NOW WE ARE MAKING BATTER
FOR THE NALESNIKI.
FLOUR,
ADD SOME MILK, SOME...
SOME VODKA.
YOU WISH.
MINERAL WATER.
CAN YOU IMAGINE IF YOU
ADDED ALL THAT VODKA?
ONE EGG AND ONE YOLK.
YOU'RE NOT YOLK-ING, REALLY.
ONE MORE TIME--WHOOP!
HERE WE GO.
PERFECT, BAKING POWDER
AND BAKING SODA.
AND THAT MINERAL WATER--
OH, THIS THING'S
GONNA BE NICE AND AIRY.
YES. TRUE VANILLA,
SUGAR.
(whistles)
A LOT OF SUGAR.
IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE VERY SWEET.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW THIS
WILL TAKE COUPLE MINUTES.
WE'RE DONE?
WE DONE.
NOW WE GET A HOT GRIDDLE
AND FLIP 'EM.
NOW WE WILL MAKE THE STUFFING
FOR THE NALESNIKI.
AND WHAT'S
GONNA GO IN THAT?
CREAM CHEESE
AND MORE SUGAR.
SO THIS
IS THE DIET PLATE?
DEFINITELY.
AND CHERRIES.
SO IT'S CREPE TIME?
CREPES TIME.
NICE AND THIN, MOVE IT AROUND.
JUST LIKE DOING A FRENCH CREPE,
ALL THE WAY UP THE SIDES,
NONSTICK PAN REALLY HELPS.
IN A MOMENT
THEY ARE READY.
SHE'S DARING, GETS RIGHT IN
THERE WITH HER FINGERS, HOT PAN.
AND YOU ALWAYS
DO IT BY HAND?
I--MYSELF, YES,
EVERYTHING HANDS.
THERE YOU GO, VOILà.
MMM, IT SMELLS AWESOME.
GET THAT VANILLA
COMING THROUGH THERE.
THIS IS THE MIXTURE.
RIGHT,
HEALTHY PORTION THERE.
YES. AND NOW I'M GOING
TO ROLL THEM. OKAY.
HOW MANY OF THESE
COME WITH AN ORDER?
FOUR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME WHIPPED CREAM ON IT.
CHOCOLATE, AND NOW ADD
A SECRET INGREDIENT--
OKAY.
TO FLAME THEM.
OH, WE GOTTA TURN
THE LIGHTS OUT FOR THIS.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
THAT WAS CRAZY.
THE VODKA JUST LIGHTS
LIKE THAT?
YEP, IT'S 96%.
WHOA!
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. I DIG THAT.
OKAY.
THE CHERRIES MAKE IT.
THAT'S A FIRST, ME
AND A DOUBLE BITE OF A DESSERT.
MMM. IT'S CREAMY.
IT'S TANGY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE CRUNCH
OF THE EXTERIOR OF THE CREPE.
HUNTER, YOU WOULD LOVE THIS,
DUDE. THAT'S AWESOME.
LOVE IT.
NICE ENDING
TO A WONDERFUL MEAL.
IF YOU WEREN'T HERE, I'D
PROBABLY BE LICKING MY PLATE.
KIELBASA DELICIOSA,
MONSIEUR.
EVERYTHING'S REALLY
BEEN FABULOUS.
WE TALKED ABOUT WHAT RESTAURANT
WE WANTED TO GO TO,
AND WE THOUGHT
POLKA--PERFECT.
IT'S REALLY A SPECIAL,
SPECIAL PLACE.
LOOK, SHE'S SO PROUD.
I REALLY ENJOYED IT.
THE FOOD WAS REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
AND YOU'RE A SWEETHEART, AND YOU
ARE DEFINITELY A CHARACTER.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
SO IS THAT
A MONEY ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHOA.
OH, GOOD.
NO, WE DO
THE SLOW MOTION. READY?
SLOW MOTION.
(both) ONE, TWO, THREE.