HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP--
FUNKY JOINTS
IN WATAUGA, TEXAS...
RIB EYE, MEDIUM RARE.
THE ENTRéES ARE JUST FABULOUS.
DUCK à L'ORANGE...
..."WOW," WHEN I
TOOK THE FIRST BITE.
AT A GAS STATION.
PHENOMENAL.
CHICKEN ALFREDO FOR YOU.
(woman) IT'S THE BEST
GAS STATION
I'VE EVER EATEN AT.
IN SEATTLE...
POLENTA'S READY
ON THE SHANK.
THERE'S A TASTE AND A FLAIR
IN EVERYTHING THEY DO.
WHERE SOME EX-PERFORMERS
ARE PUTTIN' ON A WHOLE
DIFFERENT SHOW...
AHH, HERE WE GO.
AND WHERE RAVIOLI IS TOPPED
IS TOPPED WITH ELK.
SUPER MONSTER-TENDER.
ANOTHER STELLAR DISH.
AND IN SACRAMENTO...
THREE MIXED GRILLS.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE.
IT'S ALL FRESH.
THE DIVE BAR...
GREAT LITTLE BAR
WITH THE ULTIMATE FOOD.
WHERE THE PRIME RIB...
JUST KIND OF POP IT
IN HERE.
IS SMOKIN'.
THAT'S A REALLY NICE
PIECE OF MEAT.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT
OPENING A RESTAURANT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
OKAY, LET'S SEE
WHAT WE GOT HERE.
UNLEADED, UNLEADED PLUS,
SUPER UNLEADED,
DIESEL, AND OF COURSE,
"THE BEST BREAD PUDDING."
NOW I THINK I MIGHT HAVE
LEARNED THIS AS A KID.
ONE OF THESE THINGS
IS NOT LIKE THE OTHER ONE.
BUT LISTEN, IF IT'S FUNKY,
I'LL FIND IT.
AND I MIGHT HAVE HIT
THE JACKPOT
HERE IN WATAUGA, TEXAS,
AT CHEF POINT CAFE.
I JUST GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
LAMB CHOPS IS READY.
OKAY, WE'VE GOT
CHICKEN ALFREDO FOR YOU.
IT'S THE BEST GAS STATION
I'VE EVER EATEN AT.
DUCK à L'ORANGE.
WHERE THEY'RE SERVIN' DUCK
AND ESCARGOT,
EVEN FRESH SEAFOOD
CIOPPINO.
THE FIRST THING WAS, "WOW,"
WHEN I TOOK THE FIRST BITE.
THE MENU WAS INCREDIBLE.
BLACKENED STUFFED
PORK CHOP.
CHICKEN SCAMPI.
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
RIB EYE, MEDIUM RARE.
IT TOOK US TEN MINUTES TO
DECIDE WHAT WE WANTED TO EAT.
THIS GAS STATION
HITS THE SPOT.
AND IT'S NOT BECAUSE
THEY'RE SELLIN' CHEAP GAS.
IT'S BECAUSE
OF THE GREAT FOOD.
ALL SERVED UP BY FRANSON NWAEZE
AND HIS WIFE PAULA.
THE CIOPPINO SOUP
FOR YOU, SIR.
THEY HAVE
A UNIQUE STORY.
THAT STARTED MORE
THAN 30 YEARS AGO
WHEN FRANSON MOVED
FROM NIGERIA...
THE FRESH CLAMS.
THEN MET AND MARRIED PAULA,
AND THEN THEY TRIED
TO OPEN A RESTAURANT.
THIS IS TO-GO.
BUT THE BANK
WOULDN'T LET 'EM.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO GIVE
A LOAN TO SOMEBODY
WHO DOESN'T HAVE ANY
EXPERIENCE IN THE RESTAURANT.
BUT THEY WOULD GIVE US
A LOAN FOR A GAS STATION,
SO WE SAID, "OKAY,
WE'LL TAKE IT."
AND FIGURED THEY'D BETTER SELL
MORE THAN JUST BEEF JERKY.
THE DUCK à L'ORANGE.
ACTUALLY MY FIRST TIME
TO HAVE DUCK à L'ORANGE,
AND IT'S AMAZING.
I HAVE MY OWN WAY
OF COOKING DUCK
BECAUSE EVERYBODY COMPLAIN
ABOUT DUCK BEING GREASY.
TWIST THE WINGS SO IT
DOESN'T SIT ON THE FAT
WHEN YOU'RE COOKIN'
THE DUCK.
TRUSS THE LEGS.
JUST POKE HOLES INTO IT
TO BLEED THE FATS OUT OF IT.
LIKE DUCK ACUPUNCTURE?
NOW WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT
WITH GARLIC,
ONION, PEPPER, PAPRIKA,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
SO HOW LONG WILL THIS GO
FOR AT WHAT TEMPERATURE?
350 FOR 1 HOUR.
TO GET THE SKIN CRISPY,
JUST GONNA MELT THE FAT
ON THE BOTTOM OF THE SKIN
AND POKE IT MORE.
COOK IT FOR ABOUT
ONE MORE HOUR.
SO WE'RE ROASTED,
AND WE'RE WARM.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
NOW WE'RE GONNA
DEBONE THE DUCK.
OH, THAT BAD BOY'S
REALLY RENDERED DOWN.
LOOK AT THAT. I LOVE HOW
THE LEGS JUST COME RIGHT OUT.
TO BE ABLE TO BREAK IT
OFF OF THE BONE
AND HAVE THAT IN ONE PIECE
OF DUCK WITH NO BONES IN IT--
IMPRESSIVE.
THANK YOU.
AT A GAS STATION,
REMARKABLE.
AMEN.
NOW FOR THE ORANGE SAUCE,
FRESH-SQUEEZED ORANGE JUICE.
ADD GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER.
LOOKS LIKE
A LOT OF SAUCE.
WE HAVE A LOT
OF DUCK.
SOME BLACK PEPPERCORNS.
BROWN SUGAR.
ONION FLAKE. THEN WE'RE GONNA
THICKEN IT UP WITH CORNSTARCH.
NOW HOW MUCH LONGER
WILL WE LET THIS SIMMER?
TWO TO FIVE MINUTES.
AND THAT'S THE ORANGE SAUCE.
I'M GONNA ADD
MY GARLIC BUTTER,
PICO de GALLO AND A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR ORANGE SAUCE IN IT.
AND IT'S JUST GONNA
SOAK THAT UP.
FRESH BASIL
AND PARSLEY IN IT.
READY FOR THE PASTA,
AND VOILà.
AND A LITTLE
PARMESAN CHEESE.
MMM.
OH, IT'S TENDER.
IT'S GREAT, MAN.
IT JUST FALLS OFF THE BONE.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
YOU OFFER THIS
ONCE A MONTH?
ONCE A MONTH.
I WANT TO GET ON
THAT MAILING LIST.
IT'S REALLY JUICY.
(man) SEASONED
TO PERFECTION.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
THE ENTRéES ARE
JUST FABULOUS.
WOW, THIS IS, LIKE,
NOT GAS STATION FOOD.
AND I THOUGHT,
WHY DON'T I SIT DOWN AND HAVE
A LITTLE LOBSTER BISQUE?
CHICKEN SCALOPPINI FOR YOU.
(woman) THAT'S WHAT
I ALWAYS GET,
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
I AM HAVING
THE CRAB-STUFFED SWORD FISH.
WHEN YOU COME TO A MINI-MART
CONVENIENCE GAS STATION SETUP,
YOU SHOULD STUFF IT
WITH CRAB.
SAME FOR THE CHICKEN.
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
AND THE CRAB-STUFFED
PORK CHOPS.
(man) BLACKENED STUFFED
PORK CHOP RIGHT HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
I COULD HAVE CUT THIS
WITH MY FINGER.
OOH, THAT CHOP'S
COOKED PERFECTLY.
AND THAT CRAB CAKE MIXTURE
ON THE INSIDE
IS NICE AND TENDER.
NO WONDER PEOPLE
LOVE THIS ONE.
AS RON BURGUNDY WOULD SAY,
"IT'S A TOP CHOP."
THE SAUCE
IS EXCELLENT.
AND I CAN TASTE THE BUTTER
IN IT. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
EVERYTHING THAT YOU'RE EATING
IS FRESHLY MADE.
EVEN DESSERT.
(woman) YOUR BREAD PUDDING.
ALL I'M HEARIN' ABOUT
IS BREAD PUDDING.
EVERY TIME.
REALLY?
EVEN IF I'M TOO FULL.
AND IT'S JUST
LEGIT?
IT IS. IT IS.
THE BOMB.
DEFINITELY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO
GET A BREAD PUDDING.
TEACH ME THIS MAGICAL
DESSERT, WOULD YOU, PLEASE?
A LOT OF PEOPLE
HATE BREAD PUDDING.
SO I'VE DESIGNED
A GOOD METHOD
SO EVERYBODY
WILL ENJOY IT.
PUT THE EGGS FIRST.
SUGAR.
HOW MANY POUNDS
OF SUGAR WAS THAT?
5 1/2.
VANILLA.
START IT.
ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
AND YOUR MILK
AND HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM.
HALF-AND-HALF.
THAT'S A LOT
OF LIQUID.
ALL RIGHT!
NEXT ON TRIPLE-"D,"
WHEN BREAD PUDDING
GOES WILD!
I LIKE TO USE
FRESH BREAD.
MAKE SURE THE BOTTOM OF THE PAN
IS COMPLETELY COVERED.
WE'RE JUST GONNA USE
THIS FRENCH BREAD.
THESE ARE NOT
LITTLE PIECES.
(growls)
THIS IS GOOD.
MORE BREAD?
WE WANT THE BREAD IN THE PAN
TO BE VERY, VERY TIGHT.
WHEN WE POUR LIQUID ON THIS,
THIS'LL WAY 500,000 POUNDS.
PRESS THE BREAD DOWN.
IT'S GONNA BE TIGHT.
AND WE'RE GONNA COVER
THE TOP.
MORE LIQUID?
WE WANT THE BREAD ON TOP
TO BE SOAKED ALSO.
LOOK AT THAT MESS.
IT IS SLOPPY,
BUT THEY COME OUT GOOD.
WE GOT THE PLASTIC WRAP
TO LOCK IN THE MOISTURE.
AND THEN WE'VE GOT THE HEAT
BARRIER WITH THE FOIL.
350 IN A WATER BATH
FOR WHAT? AN HOUR?
TWO HOURS.
TWO HOURS?
YES.
SO IT'S REALLY
GONNA COOK DOWN.
AND THEN WE'LL
TAKE THE TOP OFF.
WE CRUST THE TOP, AND THEN
WE FLIP THE BREAD OVER.
AND THEN BROWN
THE OTHER SIDE?
SO YOU DOUBLE-CRUST IT?
FINE, GIVE
THE SECRETS AWAY.
SHH!
OKAY, DONE.
AND THE SAUCE.
THAT'S SCRATCH-MADE, TOO,
WITH BUTTER, SUGAR AND COGNAC.
OOH, GETTIN' A LITTLE HIT
OF THAT COGNAC.
I'LL GIVE IT TO YOU, MAN.
I'M NOT A BIG DESSERT FAN,
BUT THAT--
NOT OVER-FLAVORED
AND NOT OVER-SWEET.
MMM, MY WIFE WOULD FLIP
FOR THAT. GOOD STUFF.
I LIKE THE SAUCE
THE MOST.
PROBABLY ONE OF THE SWEETEST
THINGS I'VE EVER TASTED.
CAN'T COME HERE
AND NOT GET THE BREAD PUDDING.
OH, MY GOSH.
SOME OF THE GREATEST FOOD
YOU COULD EVER HAVE.
VEGGIES FOR THE STEAKS.
I THINK THIS IS
THE BEST RESTAURANT
I'VE EVER EATEN AT.
SIR, YOU ARE A PROFESSIONAL
BIB-WEARING MACHINE.
IT WAS DEFINITELY WAY MORE
THAN I EXPECTED.
THIS REALLY IS SOMETHING UNIQUE,
SOMETHING TO BE VERY PROUD OF.
AMEN.
IF YOU TAKE ANOTHER BIG BITE,
I'LL GIVE YOU SOMETHING.
THERE YOU GO. GIVE ME
YOUR HAND. LET ME SEE.
PUT IT IN THERE.
YOU GOT YOURS. I GOT MINE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
(woman) WOW,
YOU GOT THE SAME ONE.
UP NEXT...
A LITTLE ELK.
WE'RE HEADING TO SEATTLE.
(woman) FRESH, ORGANIC,
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOR DINNER...
I LOVE EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
AND A SHOW.
♪ OH, CHELSEA ♪
(cheering)
YOU KNOW, THE NORTHWEST REGION
OF THE UNITED STATES
HAS SOME OF THE MOST UNIQUE
AND ECLECTIC RESTAURANTS
ANYWHERE.
NOW I'M HERE IN SEATTLE AT
ONE OF THOSE JOINTS, BIZZARRO.
NOW WITH A NAME LIKE THAT,
YOU MIGHT EXPECT IT TO BE
LIKE "THE TWILIGHT ZONE"
OF RESTAURANTS.
WELL, THE ONLY THING
YOU CAN EXPECT HERE
IS THE UNEXPECTED.
♪ TA DA ♪
IN THE VIBE...
WHY, COME WITH ME.
AND ON THE PLATES.
A LITTLE ELK.
'CAUSE THE OWNERS, FORMER
ACTOR JODI-PAUL WOOSTER...
ENJOY.
AND ANDREW BRAY, WHO USED
TO WORK IN THE CIRCUS...
COME ON IN.
HAD THE GOOD SENSE
NOT TO PLAY WITH THEIR FOOD.
THE PUMPKIN RAVIOLI'S AMAZING.
YOU'RE ENJOYING
THE BOLOGNESE?
I LOVE
THE BOLOGNESE.
THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT BEG
FOR THE LASAGNA.
HERE COMES YOUR SHANK.
THANKS TO SERIOUS CHEF
ROB MILLIRON.
(Rob) PUTTANESCA
AND AN ELK.
WHATEVER IS FRESH
AND IN SEASON,
THAT'S WHAT I WANT TO PUT
ON PEOPLE'S PLATES.
LIKE ORGANIC LAMB SHANKS...
WITHOUT EXCEPTION,
ONE OF THE BEST.
LOCALLY GROWN MUSHROOMS
WITH PENNE...
FRESH, ORGANIC AND DELICIOUS.
AND CHECK OUT THE LINGUINI
AND CLAM SAUCE
WITH CLAMS RIGHT OUT
OF PUGET SOUND
AND HOME-CURED PANCETTA.
SO GET ME STARTED.
I'M GONNA SLICE
MY PANCETTA.
HOUSE-MADE PANCETTA--
IT'S THE ONLY WAY TO GO.
HOUSE-MADE PANCETTA?
A COUPLE PORK BELLIES.
COVER 'EM COMPLETELY
WITH SALT.
HOW LONG DO YOU
SALT-CURE?
SEVEN DAYS.
AWESOME.
TAKE A COUPLE
OF THESE JALAPEÑOS.
SO YOU ROASTED
THE JALAPEÑOS.
YOU KNOW, THAT MELLOWS
'EM OUT A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE TAKIN' RIBS
AND SEEDS?
YEP.
YOU CAN GET A NICE LITTLE
BIT OF HEAT OUT OF THIS.
YEAH.
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME OLIVE OIL.
DON'T FORGETTA
THE PANCETTA.
THIS IS GONNA TAKE A SECOND
TO CRISP UP.
OKAY. ROASTED GARLIC.
TOSS IN MY JALAPEÑO.
HIT THIS WITH THE WHITE WINE.
TAKE A NICE,
BIG WHIFF OF IT.
I ALWAYS LIKE
MY WHITE WINE FACIAL.
SO NOW I'M GONNA
ADD SOME CLAMS.
AND I'M JUST GONNA
COVER THIS.
AND THEN WHEN THOSE
CLAMS OPEN UP,
I'M GONNA DROP
MY FRESH-MADE LINGUINI.
YOU'RE MAKIN' LINGUINI
EVERY DAY.
YEP.
SO THIS GOES
IN THE PASTA COOKER.
I'M GONNA FINISH IT
WITH A NICE, HEALTHY
PIECE OF BUTTER.
SO MY CLAMS ARE
ALL OPENED UP HERE.
ADD IN MY PASTA.
LET IT SOAK UP
SOME OF THOSE JUICES.
OH, YEAH.
THIS IS CALLED
NESTING OF THE PASTA.
PUTS THE PASTA THERE.
STANDS IT UP SO IT DOESN'T
GET LOST IN THE BOTTOM.
THAT BROTH JUST LOOKS
OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
DUDE, WHERE HAS THIS BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
SERIOUSLY, YOU GOTTA BE
LICENSED TO DO THIS.
THIS IS CRAZY.
THE ROASTED JALAPEÑO
PERFECTLY COMPLEMENTS IT.
NICE, FIRM TEXTURE
TO THE PASTA.
MMM. I WOULD CHALLENGE
ANYBODY ON THIS ONE.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE
IN THE TOP FIVE I EVER HAD.
JUST KEEP TALKIN'
ABOUT RANDOM THINGS.
I'M TRYIN' TO GET AS MANY
BITES IN AS I CAN
IN THE SEGMENT AVAILABLE.
IT'S GOT A LIGHT,
FLAVORFUL, FRESH TASTE.
THE BROTH IS DELICIOUS.
(man) BEST I'VE HAD
ALL THE WAY TO ITALY.
IT'S AS GOOD AS IT COMES.
AND IT'S FRESH.
YOU READY FOR PASTA?
YOU CAN'T MATCH YOUR ACTUAL
HOMEMADE PASTA.
IT JUST ABSORBS
ALL THE SAUCES BETTER.
MAKES A MUCH BETTER DISH.
LIKE PUTTANESCA
WITH FRESH LINGUINI.
I LOVE IT BECAUSE
IT'S SUPER SPICY.
I'M HAVING THE WHITE
TRUFFLE RIBBONS.
IN A BUTTER SAUCE WITH
SCRATCH-MADE PAPPARDELLE.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S SO GREAT.
AND EVEN GNOCCHI WITH
A CAULIFLOWER GARLIC SAUCE.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
MMM.
(mumbling with mouth full)
I WOULDN'T HAVE PUT 'EM
TOGETHER IN A MILLION YEARS.
I MEAN, I DO THE CAULIFLOWER
AND GARLIC THING.
YEAH.
BUT NOT SOMETHING HEAVY
AS A GNOCCHI.
IT'S OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
REALLY IMPRESSED.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD HERE
IS GREAT.
POLENTA'S READY
ON THE SHANK.
THERE'S A PASSION AND FLAIR
IN EVERYTHING THEY DO.
THE ATMOSPHERE IS FUN.
♪ OH, CHELSEA ♪
(cheering)
(whistles)
IF WE'RE NOT HAVING
A GOOD TIME HERE,
WE WOULDN'T BE DOING IT.
AHH, HERE WE GO.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE TO BE AROUND
A LOT OF GREAT, CREATIVE PEOPLE.
THIS JOINT IS BIZZARRO,
THOUGH, RIGHT?
EXACTLY.
THAT'S, LIKE, LICENSE
TO DO WHATEVER YOU WANT.
A LITTLE ELK.
LIKE MIXING ELK
IN YOUR RAVIOLI SAUCE.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GREAT.
THIS IS A VERY
NORTHWEST DISH
IN AN ITALIAN PREPARATION.
I'M GONNA JUST ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
YOU KNOW, ELK'S
A REAL LEAN MEAT.
RIGHT.
SO I RENDER A LITTLE PORK FAT
FROM SOME PORK BELLY
AND SEAR THE ELK IN IT.
THAT IS FLAVOR.
THIS IS ELK SHOULDER.
IT'S PERFECT FOR BRAISING.
SO IT'S BONED,
ROLLED AND TIED.
AND SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
NICE AMOUNT OF FLOUR
ON EACH SIDE.
ADD THIS IN HERE IN
THE DEEPEST PART OF THE FAT.
ALL THAT GOODNESS
COOKS IN THERE.
SEAR IT AROUND
20, 25 MINUTES.
WELL, YOU'VE CRUSTED
THAT BAD BOY.
DEFINITELY.
PULL IT OUT.
ADD MY MIREPOIX--
ONIONS, CELERY, CARROTS.
GET SOME NICE SWEETNESS
OUT OF THAT.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME SALT
AND SOME PEPPER.
TART CHERRIES,
JUST DRIED.
MMM.
GIVE IT A LITTLE
SWEET FACTOR.
I DIG IT.
DEGLAZE WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF RED WINE.
ADD SOME, UH,
GROUND TOMATOES.
WELL, THAT'S ABOUT AS
TRADITIONAL ITALIAN
AS YOU'RE GONNA GET
THERE, BROTHER.
PUT THIS BACK IN.
COVER IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF PARCHMENT PAPER.
IT'S TO CONTROL THE HEAT.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK?
ABOUT FIVE HOURS.
THE LONGER, THE BETTER.
LOW AND SLOW, BABY.
OUR ELK IS
NICE AND BRAISED.
WOW. THE DICE IS RIGHT--
BOB BARKER.
I'M GONNA TAKE MY MEAT AND THEN
THIS BRAISING LIQUID.
OH-HO.
THAT'S GONNA MAKE
UP THE SAUCE
FOR OUR POTATO ROASTED
GARLIC RAVIOLI.
NICE LITTLE TOSS
ONTO THE PLATE.
THAT'S A BIG PORTION.
A LITTLE RICOTTA CHEESE.
TOUCH OF PARSLEY.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME, DUDE.
THE ELK IS SUPER
MONSTER-TENDER,
SUCCULENT,
NOT DRIED OUT,
REALLY NICE RICH FLAVOR,
NOT GAMEY.
I CHALLENGE ANYBODY TO TELL ME
THAT THEY DON'T LIKE WILD GAME,
THEN HAVE THEM TRY THAT.
ANOTHER STELLAR DISH, MAN.
COME TO THIS CRAZY KITCHEN
AND THINK I'M GONNA
GET STUFF LIKE THAT--
THAT'S BIZZARRO.
I JUST THOUGHT
IT WAS AMAZING.
I MEAN, THE SAUCE PICKS UP
THE FLAVOR VERY WELL.
IT WAS GREAT.
I LOVE EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU.
I COME HERE FIVE NIGHTS A WEEK.
IT'S SORTA SPOILED ME ROTTEN.
NEED SOME RED SAUCE
IN ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
(Guy) THE ONE THING I'VE
BEEN IMPRESSED WITH
WITH YOU TODAY, YOU'VE REALLY
HAD FOUNDATION TO WHY YOU DO IT
AND YOU BELIEVE IN IT.
THAT'S A TRUE CHEF.
IMPRESSED.
TO BE ABLE TO COME
AND BE IN THIS ATMOSPHERE
WITH GREAT FRIENDS
AND BE ABLE TO HAVE A PLATE
OF FOOD LIKE THIS,
I MEAN,
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
THEY MAKE YOU FEEL
SPECIAL HERE.
LOVELY TO SEE YOU.
IT'S JUST A FUN
PLACE TO GO.
PEOPLE LEAVE BIZZARRO--HOW DO
YOU WANT THEM TO DESCRIBE IT?
"OH, MY GOD, I JUST ATE
AT BIZZARRO.
WHAT JUST HAPPENED TO US?"
WOW.
MIXED GRILL FOR YOU.
NEXT UP, SACRAMENTO...
GREAT LITTLE DIVE BAR
WITH THE ULTIMATE FOOD.
FOR DIVE BAR DINING...
(woman) THE PRIME RIB.
DONE THIS GUY'S WAY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA POP IT IN
HERE WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT'S DONE?
USE YOUR FINGER.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW IF YOU WATCH TRIPLE-"D,"
YOU KNOW I LOVE TO FIND
THE FUNKY JOINTS,
AND THEY'RE USUALLY IN THOSE
OBSCURE, OUT-OF-THE-WAY PLACES.
BUT I GOTTA SAY,
THIS ONE MIGHT TAKE THE CAKE.
I CAN'T EVEN FIND A STREET SIGN.
WELL, THERE'S AN ADDRESS.
BUT THERE'S NOT EVEN A SIGN ON
THE BUILDING THAT SAYS THE NAME.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE JAMIE'S,
HERE IN SACRAMENTO.
AND FROM WHAT PEOPLE
ARE TELLIN' ME,
THIS PLACE IS OFF THE HOOK.
GREAT LITTLE DIVE BAR
WITH THE ULTIMATE FOOD.
THREE MIXED GRILLS.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE.
IT'S ALL FRESH.
I GOT A HALIBUT.
CHICKEN SANDWICH UP.
I WOULD ABSOLUTELY NOT EXPECT
THIS KIND OF FOOD
TO COME OUT OF A PLACE
LIKE THIS.
(woman) PRIME RIB COMIN'
RIGHT OVER, HON.
JAMIE'S INCREDIBLE.
THAT'D BE OWNER
JAMIE BUNNELL.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO COOK?
KINDA WENT THROUGH
THE SCHOOL OF HARD KNOCKS.
HE STARTED AS A SODA JERK
WHEN HE WAS A KID
AND ENDED UP 15 YEARS LATER
WITH A JOINT OF HIS OWN.
YOU JUST NEED THE DIP.
I FOUND THE CHEAPEST
RESTAURANT I COULD FIND.
COULD YOU TELL?
DIDN'T EVEN COME
WITH A SIGN.
MIXED GRILL FOR YOU.
(Jamie) IT WAS ALWAYS
KIND OF A GUYS' HANGOUT.
YOU KNOW, COME DOWN
AND HAVE A FEW BEERS.
BUT I WANTED TO IMPROVE
THE FOOD A LITTLE BIT.
YOU WANTED TO IMPROVE IT
"A LITTLE BIT"?
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, LIKE KOBE CHUCK ROAST
AND SMOKED PRIME RIB.
SMOKED PRIME RIB.
YOU GOTTA HAVE THE PRIME RIB
WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
AND THE GARLIC STEAK SANDWICH?
HE'S DOIN' THAT
WITH FILET MIGNON.
THIS IS JUST
OFF THE CHARTS.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH THE MARINADE--
SOME WHOLE CLOVES OF GARLIC,
ADD SOME OLIVE OIL,
KOSHER SALT,
FRESHLY GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THERE'S NO SIGN OUT FRONT,
BUT EVERY MORNING,
YOU FRESH-GRIND THE PEPPER?
RIGHT.
AHH, THAT MAKES COMPLETE SENSE,
DOESN'T IT AT HOME?
WE'RE GONNA ROAST THIS
AT ABOUT 400 DEGREES
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
AND THIS IS ALL
JUST TO BEGIN
A STEAK SANDWICH.
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S GOOD.
SO THE GARLIC'S ROASTED.
OH, IT SMELLS AWESOME. WE'RE
GONNA FINALLY START MARINATING.
HEY, HEY, HEY,
I'M NOT--
WE'LL GIVE YOU AN APRON, GUY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
NO, EVEN IN MY OWN KITCHENS,
I DON'T WEAR AN APRON.
AND WHAT KIND OF MEAT ARE WE
USIN' FOR STEAK SANDWICHES?
FILET.
FILET. YOU FEEL
THE MAGIC?
TAKE THE CHAIN OFF.
IT'S LIKE MEAT BLING.
YEAH.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
CUT SOME STEAKS.
THAT'S A NICE LITTLE
2 1/2-OUNCE PIECE.
YEAH.
SO YOU JUST
PALM-TENDERIZE IT
JUST TO OPEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT?
NOW HOW LONG WILL YOU
LET IT MARINATE?
AT LEAST OVERNIGHT.
IT'S ADDING A BIT MORE
FAT BACK TO A FILET
THAT DOESN'T HAVE A LOT
OF FAT IN IT.
THIS IS OUR
MARINATED FILET.
OH, BE GENEROUS.
I'M YOUR FRIEND.
STEAKS DON'T TAKE
TOO LONG,
ABOUT 30 SECONDS A SIDE.
GONNA PUT
THE BREAD DOWN, TOO?
YEP, SWEET FRENCH ROLLS.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
A LITTLE ROASTED GARLIC.
I'D BE HAPPY
JUST WITH THIS.
TAKE SOME GOOD-QUALITY
MAYONNAISE.
IN A PIPING BAG.
COULD JUST DO
THE SPOON DOLLOP
LIKE WE DO AT ALL
THE OTHER DIVE BARS.
NOT HERE.
YOU'RE KILLIN' ME, JAMIE.
HOW DO YOU LIKE
YOUR STEAK, GUY?
MEDIUM RARE.
I HAVE NOTHING TO SAY.
(laughs)
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
GOOD.
IT'S SUPER TENDER.
THE BREAD'S GOT A NICE
ROASTED GARLIC,
A LITTLE CRUNCH TO IT.
THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
I AM SO GLAD I DON'T
LIVE CLOSE TO YOU.
I'D BE BROKE
AND OVERWEIGHT.
IT'S A GREAT SANDWICH.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY
SEARING THE GARLIC
RIGHT INTO THE STEAK.
DID ANYBODY TELL YOU
WHEN YOU BOUGHT THIS PLACE
YOU COULD'VE JUST DONE,
LIKE, BURGERS AND FRIES?
THEY TOLD ME THAT,
BUT WE'VE GOTTA GIVE THEM
SOMETHING GOOD
SO THEY'LL COME BACK.
JAMIE IS A TRUE CHEF.
ALL MY SOUPS AND SAUCES
AND STOCKS
I MAKE ON SATURDAY
AND SUNDAY.
SO YOU'RE NOT OPEN
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY,
BUT YOU'RE HERE COOKING
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
RIGHT.
THERE'S SUCH A QUALITY AND CARE
BEHIND THE FOOD.
(man) HIS TURKEY IS
ABSOLUTELY UNBELIEVABLE.
BACON HE CURES HIMSELF.
HE'S A REAL HANDS-ON GUY.
BRISKETS?
PORK SHOULDERS.
AND HE'S DOIN' HIS OWN SMOKIN'
IN A RIG OUT BACK--
EVEN THE PRIME RIB.
IT'S A UNIQUE PRIME RIB,
AND IT'S DONE PERFECTLY.
NICE-LOOKIN' RIB EYE.
NO BONE.
GIVE ME THE RUBDOWN.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA GO--
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH KOSHER SALT.
CAYENNE PEPPER. OKAY, WE GOT
SOME OLD BAY SEASONING.
OLD BAY ON--
OLD BAY IS GOOD
ON ALMOST ANYTHING.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC...
SO THIS IS YOUR
DRY RUB YOU MAKE.
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
OKAY?
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE ONION POWDER,
SOME SUGAR AND SOME DRY MUSTARD.
NOW WHERE DID YOU
LEARN THIS?
JUST PLAYIN' WITH IT.
AGAIN, AT THAT CULINARY
SCHOOL OF HARD KNOCKS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA
SHOW IT SOME LOVE.
NOW ARE YOU GONNA
LET THIS DRY RUB SIT
ON HERE FOR A BIT?
IT ACTUALLY HELPS IF YOU
LET IT SIT A LITTLE WHILE.
YOU DON'T REALLY WANT
TO LET IT SIT OVERNIGHT,
'CAUSE IT'LL ACTUALLY
PULL TOO MUCH MOISTURE
OUT OF THE RIB EYE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE HOOK HERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA LET THIS FAT...
DRIP DOWN
AND BASTE IT.
DRIP DOWN THROUGH
THAT RIB EYE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYBODY
THROW IT ON THE HONKA HOOK.
WE'RE JUST GONNA POP IT
IN HERE WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
HOW LONG YOU BEEN
DOING THIS?
22 YEARS.
ALL RIGHT, SO SIX HOURS?
HOW DO YOU KNOW IT'S DONE?
USE YOUR FINGER.
OKAY, A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE
DIGITAL THERMOMETERS
AND SCIENCE.
LOOK AT THAT.
COMES OUT REAL NICE.
COOKS REAL EVENLY.
AND THIS IS ABOUT THE PORTION
THAT YOU WOULD GET.
IS THAT THE PAUL BUNYAN CUT?
IT STAYS REALLY JUICY
COMIN' OUT.
IT'S KIND OF A HOT SMOKE.
WE'RE GONNA GIVE IT SOME AU JUS
AND SOME HORSERADISH.
I GOTTA GET RIGHT IN
THE CENTER OF THIS BAD BOY.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THAT'S A REALLY NICE
PIECE OF MEAT.
LITTLE SMOKE FLAV--
NOW WAIT A SECOND.
WHERE'D THE AU JUS
COME FROM?
THAT ACTUALLY COMES OFF
OF OUR POT ROAST.
(moans)
THIS DOESN'T MAKE
ANY SENSE.
IT'S SOME SUPER-TENDER
PRIME RIB,
BUT THAT LITTLE SMOKINESS
ON TOP OF IT
AND HOW IT'S COOKED DOWN
FOR THAT LONG--
THAT'D COMPETE WITH
ANY PRIME RIB HOUSE.
I GOTTA TELL YOU
SOMETHING, MAN,
YOU SHOULD THINK
ABOUT OPENING A RESTAURANT.
A REAL RESTAURANT.
WITH A SIGN!
WITH A SIGN.
IT'S JUICY.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S THE BALANCE
OF THE SMOKINESS,
THE TENDERNESS
OF THE MEAT.
JAMIE JUST HAS
A GREAT WAY
OF PUTTING THINGS TOGETHER.
LIKE MAYBE BRANDY,
FRESH GINGER AND SCALLOPS.
(woman) MIXED GRILL,
LESLIE?
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WE GOT FOUR
NEW YORK STEAKS.
THANK YOU.
AT JAMIE'S
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA...
(woman) PRIME RIB FOR YOU.
OWNER JAMIE BUNNELL
IS DISHIN' UP
BAR FOOD HIS WAY...
SALMON UP.
ALMOST EVERYTHING
MADE FROM SCRATCH...
I LOVE IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND A SEAFOOD SPECIAL...
(Jamie) MIXED GRILL.
THAT STARTS WITH SHRIMP SHELLS.
SHELLS HAVE A LOT
OF FLAVOR, GUY.
YOU KNOW THIS, RIGHT?
OH, I SAVE ALL MINE.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
WE'RE GONNA KIND OF SEAR THESE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE TOMATO PASTE.
THIS IS GONNA MAKE A SAUCE
FOR, UH, SEAFOOD GRILL
WHICH IS A COMBINATION
OF SCALLOPS, PRAWNS AND FISH
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF CRABMEAT--
A LITTLE FRESH
DUNGENESS CRABMEAT.
FRESH DUNGENESS CRABMEAT?
YEAH.
OF COURSE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC.
CHOPPED SHALLOTS HERE.
GOT SOME ONIONS.
GINGER. FRESH GINGER.
TO GIVE IT A LITTLE BITE,
CHILI FLAKE.
YOU JUST MAKE
THIS STUFF UP.
RIGHT.
FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
THIS IS BRANDY.
AND SOME WINE.
A LITTLE WINE.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS ALCOHOL
KIND OF COOK OFF A BIT.
WE HAVE SOME CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY.
LET THIS REDUCE DOWN.
STRAIN OUT THE SHELLS.
BREAK THIS DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU LEARN THIS
IN DIVE BAR 101.
THIS IS WHAT
THEY TEACH YOU.
THIS SHOULD JUST
BE SOUP!
NOW WHAT'S GONNA GO ON?
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF FENNEL
AND SOME LEEKS TO IT.
ONCE IT'S SAUTéED UP,
WE'RE GONNA ADD FRESH BASIL.
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
MORE FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
THESE ARE GONNA BE SAUTéED
AND THEN PUT IN TO THE SAUCE.
RIGHT.
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA FINISH IT
WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF HEAVY CREAM.
HEY, WE'RE NOT DONE?
THIS IS GONNA COOK DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
SO WHILE THAT REDUCES,
WE'RE GONNA COOK
THE SEAFOOD.
RIGHT.
NICE.
DROP THESE INTO
SOME SEASONED FLOUR--
JUST FLOUR, SALT AND PEPPER.
FISH IS GONNA TAKE
THE LONGEST.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
NOW DOWN WITH THE SCALLOPS,
'CAUSE YOU DON'T WANT
TO OVER COOK THOSE,
AND THE SHRIMP GO SUPER FAST.
OKAY, SO NOW
ALL THE SEAFOOD'S DONE.
PUT A PIECE OF FISH
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
COUPLE PRAWNS. I'M GONNA
GIVE YOU A SCALLOP.
I'M GONNA PUT SOME FRESH
DUNGENESS CRABMEAT ON HERE.
GOT IT.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME BASIL,
JULIENNED LEEKS,
A LITTLE BIT MORE FENNEL,
A LITTLE CORNSTARCH...
AND PUT A LITTLE
DREDGE ON IT.
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
AND FRY IT.
ALL RIGHT, LET ME LOOK
AT THAT SAUCE NOW.
GET A LITTLE TEXTURE.
IF THIS TASTES ONE-TENTH
AS GOOD AS IT LOOKS...
MMM.
THAT WOULD BE GOOD
ON JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
THE SCALLOP IS DONE
PERFECTLY RIGHT.
THE SHRIMP ARE NICE.
BIG U-12s.
MMM, I KNOW FOR A FACT
I DIDN'T DRIVE UP TO THIS PLACE
EXPECTING TO GET
EVEN 1% OF THAT.
THAT'S OFF THE HOOK.
IT'S WHAT I WOULD
CALL FANTASTIC.
EXCEPTIONALLY CREAMY
AND A LITTLE BIT SPICY.
IT'S FABULOUS, JUST THE WAY
JAMIE DOES IT EVERY TIME.
THE FOOD JUST MAKES
YOUR TASTE BUDS GO INSANE.
IT'S JUST ONE OF THOSE PLACES
YOU FEEL AT HOME.
YOUR SMOKED
PRIME RIB, BABY.
(Jamie) YOU PUT SOME GOOD FOOD
IN THEIR TUMMIES,
THROW TWO COCKTAILS
DOWN THEIR THROAT,
AND THEY START TO LIKE YOU,
YOU KNOW?
CRAZY HOW THAT HAPPENS.
THAT'S HOW I GOT
ALL MY BUDDIES.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE-"D."
NO SIGN.
I MEAN,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
PERFECT.
TELL ME THAT'S NOT
LEGIT, HUH?