HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI.
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
OLD-TIME FAVORITES...
GREAT THING ABOUT IT
IS IT DOESN'T CHANGE.
IN PORTLAND...
GRILLED CHEESE
AND TOMATO SOUP.
AT THE LUNCH COUNTER
THAT FEELS LIKE 1925.
IT HAS THAT SENSE
OF HISTORY.
AND THEY'RE DOING
ALL OF THIS...
WE'VE GOT
A MAC AND CHEESE.
THE MAC AND CHEESE
IS HEAVEN.
WITHOUT A STOVE.
YOU'D BE DANGEROUS
WITH A FULL KITCHEN.
IN THE MOUNTAINS OF IDAHO...
STEAK SANDWICH.
A LOCAL LANDMARK...
HILLTOP T.B.A.
MONUMENTOUS.
AN IDAHO ICON.
DOING BIG FOOD...
A LOT OF NACHOS.
AND BIG FLAVORS.
MMM, THAT IS GOOD.
THAT'S ALWAYS NICE--
WHEN YOU GET A NICE JUICE RUN.
AND IN MIAMI...
WHOA.
A FAMILY JOINT
DOING CUBAN FAVORITES...
THEY CALL IT,
UH, CARITAS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THIS IS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
THIS IS A BEAN CRACKER.
TALK ABOUT GETTIN' A SHIRT TAIL
CAUGHT UP IN--(grumbles)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN DOWNTOWN PORTLAND, OREGON,
AND, MAN, IS THERE A LOT GOIN'
ON--LOVE COMIN' TO THIS TOWN.
THEY'VE GOT SUCH A STRONG
POSITION ON FOOD--
I MEAN, FROM THE TRADITIONAL
TO THE INTERNATIONAL
TO THE UNIQUE.
AND SPEAKIN' OF UNIQUE,
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT BLUEPLATE,
WHERE THIS DUDE IS CRANKIN' OUT
THE LUNCH COUNTER CLASSICS
AND DOIN' SOME OLD-SCHOOL
HANDMADE SODAS. MONEY.
HERE'S A GRILLED CHEESE...
OH, THANK YOU.
WITH TOMATO SOUP.
IT'S A GREAT LITTLE SPOT
FOR LUNCH.
WE GOT A CHOCOLATE MALT.
IT'S LIKE 1925,
LIKE IT WAS A PHARMACY
TURNED SODA FOUNTAIN.
JUST LIKE TRAINED CHEF
JEFF REITER IMAGINED
WHEN HE FIRST SAW
THIS SPACE FOR RENT...
AND I CONVINCED THE OWNER
OF THE BUILDING
TO SEE MY VISION.
EVEN THOUGH THE PLACE
DIDN'T EVEN HAVE A KITCHEN.
TWO MACS, FIVE MINUTES.
YOU'RE LIVING OFF
OF THESE ELECTRIC COOKTOPS.
THIS IS CALLED
A RESTAURANT DUDE
MAKIN' IT WORK.
GO FOR TABLE THREE.
THE POINT WAS TO MAKE SURE
THAT PEOPLE FELT LIKE THEY
WERE STEPPING BACK IN TIME.
THERE YOU ARE.
HOW DID YOU COME UP
WITH YOUR MENU?
WE WERE LOOKIN' FOR THINGS
THAT WERE PRE-WAR--
GRILLED CHEESE
AND TOMATO SOUP.
I MEAN, THAT'S
THE PERFECT COMBINATION.
ALL RIGHT, WE GOT
A MAC AND CHEESE.
TWO SLIDERS UP.
YEAH, THOSE ARE PRE-WAR, TOO,
FIRST MADE POPULAR
BACK IN THE '20s.
IT'S LIKE A PINT-SIZED
HAMBURGER.
EVERYBODY WANTED SLIDERS.
THIS IS WHERE YOU'RE GONNA
GOURMET US A LITTLE BIT.
AN UPSCALE PLAY ON TRADITIONAL
MIDWESTERN SLIDER--
WE GOT SOME CANOLA OIL,
SOME ONION.
WE GOT SOME GARLIC. WE GOT
ITALIAN BLEND SEASONING--
A LITTLE BASIL, THYME,
ROSEMARY, OREGANO--
CHILI POWDER--
AND A CAYENNE-BASED
CHILI POWDER.
SALT, A LITTLE PEPPER.
WE REALLY JUST WANT
TO TOAST THOSE SPICES
AND SOFTEN THE ONION.
JUST SO WE'RE NOT GONNA BITE
INTO A CRUNCHY ONION
WHEN WE BITE
INTO THE SLIDER.
YEAH, WE KINDA--
WE KINDA WANT A LITTLE TOOTH
TO THE ONIONS.
SET THAT ASIDE.
AND OVER HERE WE GOT THE SECRET
TO A GOOD HAMBURGER--
HALF PORK AND HALF BEEF.
I AGREE WITH YOU ON THAT.
WE LOVE IT IN MEATBALLS.
WE LOVE IT IN MEATLOAF.
WHY WOULDN'T WE LOVE IT IN A--
IN A HAMBURGER OR IN A SLIDER?
EXACTLY. OUR ONION MIX--
SO GET IN THERE REALLY GOOD.
SO I'M GONNA MAKE
ABOUT PING PONG BALL-SIZE--
WE'RE JUST GONNA ROLL 'EM UP
AS TIGHT AS WE CAN.
IF YOU COULD GRAB
THE BUTTER.
WHERE DO YOU
WANT IT, BROTHER?
JUST ALL OVER THE PLACE.
SO WE JUST TAKE THESE BALLS,
AND WE LET 'EM START
TO GET A LITTLE CARAMELIZED
ON THE BOTTOM.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR POTATO ROLLS,
POP THEM ON THE BUTTER
BEFORE THE FAT GETS TOO HOT...
MM-HMM.
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
TO SQUISH OUT ALL MY GOOD FAT,
BUT I NEED TO MAKE 'EM THIN,
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
SQUISH 'EM DOWN, GIVE 'EM A LID,
LET 'EM COOK AWAY.
WE'RE GONNA SHRED SOME CHEESE.
WE USE TILLAMOOK CHEDDAR CHEESE.
THAT'S A COASTAL TOWN WITH A LOT
OF COWS HERE IN OREGON,
AND THEY MAKE
FABULOUS CHEESE.
SO WE'RE GONNA GIVE
THE BURGERS A QUICK FLIP.
AND SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
PUT THESE PILES--
WHEN YOU MAKE A CHEESEBURGER,
SHRED YOUR CHEESE.
IT MELTS A LOT BETTER.
I AGREE.
WOULD YOU LIKE BACON
ON YOUR BURGER?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK YES.
YES.
OKAY. SO WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A COUPLE PINCHES OF BACON BITS,
AND WE'RE GONNA LID THIS UP
TO GET A NICE STEAM ON THAT BUN.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR BASIL MAYONNAISE.
NOTHING REALLY FANCY ABOUT IT--
TAKE MAYONNAISE,
DELI MUSTARD--
IT'S GOT SOME EXTRA SPICE--
FRESH PESTO--BASIL WITH JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL--
A LITTLE BIT OF RICE VINEGAR,
NOT MUCH,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
WHISK THAT UP REALLY WELL.
THIS IS THE BEST PART
OF THE WHOLE BURGER
IS THIS NICE EXTRA
COUPLE HUNDRED CALORIES.
WOW.
WE GOT OUR JUICY CHEESEBURGERS,
THE MESSIER THE BETTER.
YEAH.
WHAT WAS THE COW'S NAME?
HARRIET. SHE LIVES OUT IN
TILLAMOOK COUNTY ON THE COAST.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
THAT IS A TON OF FLAVOR.
YOU COULD'VE JUST TAKEN
THE POTATO ROLL
WITH THAT BASIL MAYO
AND SOME MELTED CHEESE,
AND IT WOULD'VE ROCKED.
THIS IS THREE TIMES THE FLAVOR
PROFILE OF A CHEESEBURGER.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THE SAUCE THAT HE HAS ON IT
IS INCREDIBLE--
THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
SUPER RICH AND DELICIOUS...
MMM.
IT'S AWESOME.
IF YOU GOTTA
GET A COUPLE SLIDERS,
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME TO,
RIGHT HERE.
OR SOME POT ROAST...
I HAVE AN EGG CREAM.
THERE YOU GO.
OR REAL FOUNTAIN DRINKS.
IT HAS THAT SENSE
OF HISTORY.
A PERFECT OLD-TIME
SODA FOUNTAIN--
JEFF MAKES HIS
OWN SODAS.
USING RECIPES FROM 1925.
PURPLE HAZE?
THIS ONE HE'S MAKING
OUT OF DRIED HIBISCUS FLOWERS.
WOW. IT'S DEFINITELY SWEET.
I DON'T REALLY ENJOY
SWEETS THAT MUCH.
I LIKE GETTING THOSE REAL SHARP,
BRIGHT FLAVORS IN THERE.
IT'S LIKE SNOW CONES
GONE WILD.
SODA?
THANK YOU.
IT MAKES ME FEEL
LIKE I'M A LITTLE KID.
SO DOES THIS.
I GOT A GRILLED CHEESE
AND TOMATO SOUP.
(Guy) MY 3-YEAR-OLD RYDER IS
THE QUINTESSENTIAL JUDGE
OF ALL TOMATO SOUP
AND GRILLED CHEESE.
I'M GONNA CHANNEL
THE RYDER.
YEP, PAST THE 3-INCH.
HE WOULD COME DOWN HERE
LIKE THIS, STIR IT.
WOW. IF HE LIKES IT,
HE'LL DOUBLE-FIST IT.
I THINK THIS WOULD BE
A RYDER DOUBLE-FIST.
ON A COOL DAY IN PORTLAND,
IT'S HARD TO BEAT.
OR THIS ONE.
(Jeff) MAC COMIN' OUT.
THE MAC AND CHEESE
IS HEAVEN.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE BACON-MUSHROOM
MAC AND CHEESE
WITH TILLAMOOK PEPPER JACK.
WE'RE GONNA NEED SOME OIL
IN THE PAN.
AND WE WANT TO GET SOME BACON
WITH A GOOD AMOUNT OF BACON FAT.
WE GOT THE ONIONS, AND WE'RE
GONNA NEED A LITTLE SALT.
WE'RE GONNA GET SOME GARLIC
IN THERE AND SOME HERBS--
BASIL, THYME,
ROSEMARY, OREGANO.
YOU AND THAT
ITALIAN SEASONING.
IT'S THE SECRET INGREDIENT.
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSHROOMS,
THEN WE'RE GONNA LID THAT UP,
LET IT STEAM
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
AND THEN COME OVER
AND MAKE THE CHEESE SAUCE.
YEP.
DIG IT.
STARTS WITH ONIONS AND GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT,
ONE PART CHICKEN BROTH,
TWO PARTS CREAM.
GOT IT.
WHEN THAT COMES UP TO A BOIL,
WE NEED TO THICKEN THAT UP...
(whistles)
WITH SOME ROUX--FLOUR
AND BUTTER COOKED TOGETHER.
ADD SOME PEPPER JACK CHEESE,
STIR THAT IN.
WE GOT A BOWL OF LARGE
ELBOW MACARONI, AL DENTE.
THE MUSHROOM-ONION-BACON
WITH ITALIAN SEASONING.
FRESH CHEESE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA GIVE THAT
A NICE STIR.
SO WHEN SOMEONE COMES IN,
THIS IS HOW IT GOES.
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT.
BREADCRUMBS FOR THE TOP,
AND THAT GOES IN
UNDER THE BROILER
FOR JUST ABOUT TWO,
THREE MINUTES AND READY TO EAT.
WOW.
MMM, THAT'S THE WAY
TO ROCK IT.
THIS HAS GOOD CREAMINESS.
THIS HAS GREAT FLAVOR.
THE NOODLE YOU CHOSE,
THE LITTLE RIGATA ELBOW--PRIMO.
BACON AND MUSHROOM--YOU JUST
CANNOT GO WRONG WITH IT
NO MATTER WHAT. THIS IS
YOUR MAC AND CHEESE, BABY.
(man) I DON'T THINK I'VE HAD
ANY MAC AS GOOD AS THAT BEFORE.
REALLY?
YOU COULD JUST EAT
PLATES OF IT. IT'S HEAVEN,
ONE AND TWO
COMIN' UP.
FOR A DUDE THAT REALLY HAS
NO KITCHEN,
YOU SURE CRANK OUT
SOME GOOD PRODUCT, BRO.
GOT TWO SLIDERS
WITH MAC.
HE KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING HERE.
IT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
AMERICAN COMFORT FOOD.
MONEY. MONEY.
DUDE, I GOTTA TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
YOU'D BE DANGEROUS
WITH A FULL KITCHEN,
CAPITAL "D" DANGEROUS.
HIT THE MUSIC.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADING TO IDAHO...
THIS IS ABOUT AS PERFECT
AS IT GETS.
FOR A STEAK SANDWICH...
NICE, LEAN MEAT.
WITH THE WORKS.
VEGETABLE, HERBY
MAYONNAISE-BASED MOUTHFUL
OF DELICIOUSNESS.
THAT'S ONE WHOLE WORD
HERE IN BOISE.
I'M HERE
AT THE HIGHLAND VALLEY SUMMIT,
ABOUT 15 MILES OUTSIDE OF BOISE,
AT A LOCAL LANDMARK
THAT'S BEEN RESURRECTED.
YOU SEE, ON TRIPLE "D," IT'S
NOT ALWAYS JUST ABOUT THE FOOD,
IT'S ABOUT THE HISTORY, TOO.
WELCOME TO DONN'S
HILLTOP KODIAK GRILL.
KODIAK BURGER MEDIUM!
GOOD OLD TRADITIONAL PLACE
UP ON THE MOUNTAINTOP.
YEP.
GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR,
AND IT'S A LOT OF FOOD.
NACHOS WITH BEEF!
BIG!
IT'S BIG?
THERE WAS
A LOT OF NACHOS.
HILLTOP T.B.A.
MONUMENTOUS.
AN IDAHO ICON.
IT'S BEEN HERE
SINCE 1952.
BUT IT WAS ON ITS LAST LEG
WHEN DANARAE CLOR
BOUGHT IT...
ORDER UP!
AND BROUGHT IT BACK.
YOUR KODIAK SOUP.
BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
WHEN SHE OPENED
THIS PLACE.
YOU WERE GONNA HOLD IT
TO ITS ROOTS.
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S AWESOME.
WE NEEDED IT TO BE
WHAT IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
IT'S A NICE PLACE
YOU CAN RELAX
AND ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
SO THIS FORMER REALTOR...
GRILLED STEAK.
TOOK A CRASH COURSE
FROM SOME BUDDIES
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
ORDER UP.
AND STARTED
SERVING BIG FOOD...
I'M TAKING THIS HOME
FOR THREE MORE DAYS.
DONE RIGHT.
(woman) BIG BEAR.
(man) YEP.
THE POT ROAST SANDWICH,
IT HAS A LOT OF FLAVOR.
AND THERE'S A NEW HIT
ON THE MENU.
STEAK SANDWICH.
NICE, LEAN MEAT,
FLAVOR'S REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THIS BEAUTIFUL
NEW YORK TRI-TIP STEAK.
LET'S DO THE RUB. WE'RE GONNA
START--PAPRIKA, CAYENNE
CURRY...
AND YOUR MADRAS CURRY.
YEAH. PEPPER...
BLACK PEPPER.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
BROWN SUGAR...
YOU GOT SOME THYME.
AND SOME KOSHER SALT.
THEN I'M JUST GONNA
MIX IT ALL UP HERE,
PUT THE MEAT IN IT AND ROLL IT
AND JUST GIVE IT A GOOD--
(growls)
WHAT DID YOU
JUST GIVE IT?
WHAT DID YOU JUST GIVE IT?
YOU GAVE IT A GOOD...
WELL, I WENT--
(growls)
YOU GAVE IT A GOOD--
THAT'S THE WHOLE
KODIAK THING, HUH?
YEAH, IT IS.
(growls)
YEAH, IT'S THAT BEAR IN US.
AND WAIT TILL YOU TASTE IT.
I WILL WAIT UNTIL I TASTE IT,
'CAUSE IT'S NOT READY.
PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
WELL, LET'S GET IT
IN THERE.
WELL, GIDDYAP.
WE'RE GONNA GO 325,
30 TO 40 MINUTES.
NOW WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
THE RéMOULADE.
THIS IS--
I JUST CALL IT A...
PLEASE TELL ME THAT THOSE WORDS
ARE ON THE SCREEN BELOW ME HERE.
THAT'S ONE WHOLE WORD
HERE IN BOISE.
(bell dings)
WE GOT THE LEMON JUICE,
YELLOW ONIONS,
YELLOW MUSTARD.
THANK YOU ON THAT.
GARLIC, HORSERADISH--
YUM, LIKE IT SPICY HOT--
SCALLIONS, KETCHUP.
YOU DON'T WANT TO TELL ME
IT'S TOMATO KETCHUP?
OR "TO-MAH-TO" KETCHUP.
DON'T START.
HA. SOME DIJON.
WE'RE GONNA GO FOR OUR CELERY,
PARSLEY, CAYENNE--MMM.
MAYONNAISE, I'M JUST GONNA TOSS
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT...
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
NOW WE CAN ADD OUR OLIVE OIL
VERY SLOWLY.
OKAY, SO THIS IS DONE.
WE'RE DONE.
THE MEAT'S STILL ROASTING.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA DO
THE AU JUS. 4 CUPS OF WATER.
AU JUS TIME.
BLESS YOU.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
WAITING FOR THAT?
OKAY, AS SOON AS HE SAYS IT,
OOH, I'M ON IT.
SAYS--
JUST LIKE THAT--
JUST LIKE A HALF A SECOND...
SAID WHAT?
DID YOU NOTICE?
AU JUS.
BLESS YOU.
YEAH. THANK YOU.
BEEF BASE,
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF CAJUN,
CUTTINGS FROM OUR PRIME RIB.
A LOT OF GREAT FLAVOR.
CERTIFIED BLACK ANGUS--
BEAUTIFUL.
AND WE WANT TO GET IT
UP INTO A BOIL.
OKAY.
SO I'M GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WORCESTERSHIRE,
SOME TABASCO.
AND AGAIN,
JUST RANDOMNESS.
AND TO TOP IT OFF,
AN ICE-COLD AMBER BEER.
I'M GONNA LET IT SIMMER,
AND THEN I'M GONNA
LET IT RENDER DOWN.
LOOK AT YOU
WITH YOUR CULINARY TERMS.
I WATCH
THE FOOD NETWORK.
EVIDENTLY.
SO THE MEAT'S DONE.
BRING IT OUT. LET IT REST.
SLICE IT THIN.
ON THE FLAT-TOP--
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
MAKING THE SANDWICH.
WE ARE.
OKAY.
WE PUT SOME
CLARIFIED BUTTER DOWN.
ON MY ONIONS, I'VE ADDED JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF POWDERED SUGAR.
POWDERED SUGAR.
JUST GIVES IT
A LITTLE EXTRA DIMENSION.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSHROOMS.
AND THIS IS WHERE OUR AU JUS
COMES INTO PLAY.
NOW THAT'S STEAMING, WE'RE GONNA
PUT SOME PEPPER JACK ON THAT,
LET THAT START TO MELT.
AND WE'RE GONNA GRAB
THIS GORGEOUS SOURDOUGH BREAD.
WE'RE GONNA USE
OUR CLARIFIED BUTTER AGAIN.
HOLY PAUL BUNYAN.
YEAH. GIVE IT A GOOD COAT.
YEAH, YOU DID.
TOSS HER DOWN.
WITH THE POWDERED-SUGARED
ONIONS.
REMEMBER THAT RéMOULADE
WE MADE?
YEP.
THIS IS WHERE IT GOES, RIGHT
HERE, JUST A LITTLE BIT HERE.
SHREDDED LETTUCE,
FRESH CUT TOMATOES.
AND SIX MORE PEOPLE
TO COME EAT IT WITH ME.
THERE WE GO.
SAUTéED MUSHROOMS AND ONIONS,
TOP PIECE OF BREAD.
YOU KNOW HOW TO THE HUNCH?
WELL, I HAVE THE HUNCH CARD.
HOW CONVENIENT.
FIRST IS THE STANCE.
OKAY.
OKAY. GET YOUR FEET
OUT THERE.
GOT IT.
I MEAN, YOU WANT
TO POSITION YOURSELF.
YOU--YOU'RE BRINGIN' IN
SOME THUNDER. OKAY?
YEAH.
THEN THERE'S
THE GRAB AND GRIP.
OKAY.
GET YOUR ELBOWS OUT.
ELBOWS OUT.
OKAY. NOW ROTATE THIS UP.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
THE MEAT REALLY IS THE WINNER
ON THIS--SUPER TENDER.
THAT'S ALWAYS NICE,
WHEN YOU GET A NICE JUICE RUN
DOWN INTO YOUR BLING.
I THINK THE AU JUS REALLY MAKES
IT COME TOGETHER.
YOUR POWDERED SUGAR ONION
THING--
(sighs)
YOU WANT TO TRY THIS?
IT'S FANTASTIC.
I CAN ONLY EAT HALF
AND LEAVE HALF FOR TOMORROW.
IT'S VERY IDAHO.
IT WAS A SPORTSMAN'S--WHERE,
YOU KNOW, THE HUNTERS COME UP...
(Guy) OKAY.
AND THIS IS
WHERE THEY'D HANG OUT.
FISH AND CHIPS.
MMM.
AND IT'S PART OF THE CONCEPT
OF WHY EVERYTHING IS SO BIG...
RIGHT.
SO WE CAN SHARE.
FROM THE SANDWICHES...
YOU HAVIN'
THE WHOLE TURKEY?
THE WHOLE TURKEY.
TO THE NACHOS.
(Danarae) DEBBIE!
AND GET A LOAD OF THIS...
KODIAK BURGER,
SWEET POTATO FRIES.
A 1/2-POUNDER
WITH A HUNK OF KIELBASA.
JUST A VERY INTERESTING
COMBINATION.
AND A LITTLE POP
THAT YOU JUST DON'T GET
WHEN YOU HAVE A HAMBURGER.
I DON'T THINK
WE'VE EVER SEEN
WHERE WE'RE GONNA DO GROUND BEEF
AND SAUSAGE ON THE SAME THING.
WE FLAME-BROIL IT, SO YOU GET
THAT LOVELY SMOKINESS AS WELL.
FIRST I WANT TO GET
THAT SMOKINESS GOING, RIGHT?
(Guy) "BUTTER-FLAVORED
SEASONING SPRAY."
(Danarae) YEAH.
SALT AND PEPPER--
I'M GONNA GRAB MY BREAD.
A LITTLE BIT
OF CLARIFIED BUTTER,
AND WE'RE GONNA
BROWN THAT UP.
GIVE HER A FLIP.
THERE SHE IS.
FLIP OUR KIELBASA.
AND WE'RE GONNA
GET OUR CHEESE ON NOW.
OKAY.
WE'VE GOT THAT GOING.
IT LOOKS LIKE OUR BREAD'S
PRETTY CLOSE HERE.
THE BURGER IS SO JUICY
AND SO FLAVORFUL ON ITS OWN,
THAT I DON'T PUT A STICK
OF ANYTHING ON IT.
OH, AMEN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR KIELBASA
RIGHT ON TOP OF OUR BURGER.
WOW. LOOK AT THE JUICE
THAT'S COMIN' OUT OF THAT.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
THAT SAUSAGE ON IT--WHY HAVE I
NEVER THOUGHT OF THAT?
THAT IS THE WAY
TO ROCK IT.
YOU'RE EXACTLY RIGHT TO NOT PUT
ANY SAUCE ON THIS. MMM.
PUT YOUR GLASSES ON AT HOME--
3-D BURGER.
WOW, NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S GOTTA BE
A PRETTY POPULAR BURGER.
IT'S A GOOD ONE.
WELL, I LOVE THE LITTLE TASTE
OF SAUSAGE IN WITH HAMBURGER.
ONLY HALF?
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL
IT'S GONNA BE?
IT'S ALL I CAN DO.
YEAH, THAT'S A 1/2 POUND.
(Danarae) LINDSEY, CHEF SALAD.
YOU'RE UP.
I LOVE IT UP HERE
IN THE MOUNTAINS.
THIS IS ABOUT AS PERFECT
AS IT GETS.
AND YOUR STEAK SANDWICH.
THANK YOU.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
OUT OF THE WAY,
BUT DEFINITELY WORTH IT.
NICE JOB, GIRL.
WAY TO GO.
THANKS.
PERFORMING NIGHTLY.
NEXT STOP, MIAMI...
ALL RIGHT.
IF WE WANT SEAFOOD,
WE COME HERE.
FOR LOBSTER...
THE BEST.
KETCHUP AND A TRIP
TO THE FRYER.
GREAT TEXTURE,
REALLY NICE CRUNCH. WOW.
TASTY.
YEAH.
YOU CATS ARE SO GONNA
DIG THIS ONE,
'CAUSE TRIPLE "D" KNOWS
NO BOUNDARIES.
I SAY "MIAMI," MOST PEOPLE THINK
SOUTH BEACH RESTAURANTS,
BUT I'M GONNA TAKE YOU
TO AN AREA
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO GO TO,
LITTLE HAVANA,
A PREDOMINATELY CUBAN COMMUNITY
THAT HAS THIS PLACE,
LA CAMARONERA,
WHERE SINCE '73,
THE GARCIA FAMILY HAS BEEN
SERVIN' UP FRESH SEAFOOD
CUBAN-STYLE.
EVERYTHING FRIED--
WE DON'T GRILL ANYTHING.
IT'S THE SNAPPER.
FRIED LOBSTER--
THE BEST.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
FRIED SHRIMP
WITH YELLOW RICE
AND GREEN PLANTAINS--
DELICIOUS.
THIS PLACE ISN'T JUST TRADITION.
IT'S A LANDMARK.
ONE SHRIMP COMING UP!
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
15, 20 YEARS.
THE GREAT THING ABOUT IT
IS IT DOESN'T CHANGE.
HERE YOU GO!
AND DAVID GARCIA IS NOT ABOUT
TO START CHANGING IT NOW...
YOU WANT
A BIG ONE, BOSS?
36 YEARS AFTER HIS FAMILY
OPENED THE JOINT.
(speaking Spanish)
MY DAD STILL WORKS HERE.
MY UNCLE WHO'S 82
STILL WORKS HERE.
AND THEY'RE STILL CRANKIN' OUT
THE FAMILY RECIPES...
(man) UNA MINUTA.
THE TRADITIONAL
CUBAN WAY.
THEY DO GROUPER,
KINGFISH.
FRIED OYSTERS
COMING OUT NOW.
SHRIMP SANDWICH,
SHRIMP SANDWICH ALWAYS.
SHRIMP SANDWICH
MAKES IT?
AND GET THIS ONE--
LOBSTER WITH A KETCHUP SAUCE
FRIED RIGHT IN.
ONCE I CAME HERE
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
I DON'T EAT IT ANYWHERE ELSE.
(whistles)
FLORIDA LOBSTER HERE.
SO WHERE'S THE CLAWS?
THE CLAWS ARE ONLY
ON THE MAINE LOBSTER.
EAT THE TAIL MEAT ONLY?
WE EAT THE TAIL MEAT ONLY.
WE'RE GONNA PREPARE THIS LOBSTER
UP--JUST SPLIT THE TAIL IN HALF.
WOW, IT'S GOT A PINKISH MEAT
VERSUS THE WHITE WE SEE
IN THE MAINE.
CORRECT.
TAKE THE MEAT OUT.
CUT THIS INTO PIECES.
PUT IT IN OUR RED SAUCE.
WHAT'S IN THE RED SAUCE?
LEMON JUICE.
I'M SURE YOU
GOT THAT--UGH.
OKAY.
UGH.
GOT A LITTLE WET THERE?
THIS IS WHERE THEY CLEAN
AND PROCESS A BUNCH OF FISH,
AND I'M IN A FLIP-FLOP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME SALT, COMINO...
I HAVE SCALES
GROWING ON MY FEET.
PEPPER, GROUND GARLIC.
IT LOOKS LIKE WE'RE
GONNA ADD KETCHUP NOW.
I'LL BE OVER HERE.
WANT TO TRY IT?
FOUL.
THIS IS ALL
JUST FOR LOBSTER?
AND OUR SHRIMP.
SO NOW WE ARE SET
TO MAKE CEMENT.
SERIOUSLY, THIS IS WHAT WE'RE
GONNA MIX IT WITH?
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
GONNA MIX IT WITH.
OKAY. WE'RE DIGGING
DEEP DOWN
INTO THE BASE
OF THE VOLCANO.
(sighs)
A HOST'S JOB
IS NEVER DONE.
THE WARM WATER LOBSTER,
THE KETCHUP SAUCE--
THE RED SAUCE
AND SOME FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE?
YEP. DIP THIS INTO THE, UH,
RED SAUCE.
WE'RE NOT REALLY MAKING
A LOT OF SENSE RIGHT NOW
HERE IN MY CULINARY WORLD,
BUT I'M ENJOYING
WHERE WE'RE GOING.
THROW THIS NOW
IN THE FRYER.
I'M GONNA GET KICKED OUT OF
THE CULINARY CLUB ON THIS ONE.
IT'S LIKE THE COMMUNITY POOL
OF FLAVOR TOWN.
YOU'RE THE BIG LIFEGUARD.
THAT'S IT.
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
YOU MAY WANT TO THROW SOME LIME,
SOME HOT SAUCE IF YOU'D LIKE.
MMM. THERE'S NOTHIN'
WRONG WITH THAT.
YEAH.
GREAT TEXTURE,
REALLY NICE CRUNCH--
WOW.
TASTY.
YEAH. OKAY, NOW THE HOT SAUCE,
IT'S PRETTY MILD...
NOT REALLY.
IT'S FRESH, TENDER,
NICE AND CRISPY.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WITH
THE LOBSTER AND THE SHRIMP.
ALL THE FISH,
I LIKE.
I LOVE THE FACT THAT I CAN GO
AND PICK OUT A FISH.
THIS ONE?
UH-HUH.
ALL RIGHT.
THEY FRY IT.
IT COMES OUT PERFECT.
WHOLE FISH
AND FISH SANDWICH.
I HAVE A MINUTA SANDWICH.
LET ME HAVE
SOME MINUTA SANDWICHES.
TASTES AMAZING.
WE'VE GOT OUR
YELLOWTAIL SNAPPER HERE
FOR OUR MINUTA SANDWICH.
MINUTA SANDWICH IS ACTUALLY
THE, UH, STYLE OF THE, UH--
OF THE CUT,
WHICH IS BUTTERFLY.
DO WE LEAVE THE TAIL ON?
WE ARE GONNA LEAVE
THE TAIL ON.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA SCALE THIS.
SO NOW YOU COMB IT.
WHOA. THAT'S SCARY.
DIP THIS IN SOME WATER, MAKE
SURE ALL THE SCALES ARE OFF.
JUST AT THE TOP--
LIKE A SURGEON
WITH A MACHETE.
NOW HOW MANY OF THESE FISH
WILL YOU GUYS DO IN A DAY?
ABOUT 400.
PULL OFF HERE.
OH! YAHTZEE!
MAKE SURE WE GET THESE OUT.
THAT'S THE LITTLE BONES.
LITTLE BONES THERE.
SO THAT'S DONE.
IT'S ALL GOOD TO GO.
YEAH. WE MARINATE THIS.
WE GOT SOME WATER HERE,
LEMON JUICE, GROUND GARLIC.
JUST EYEBALL
MEASUREMENT?
YEP. GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
(whistles)
NOW WE USE
SOME CUMIN, SALT.
MIX IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
AND NOW WE'RE
AT ABOUT 3 GALLONS.
AND THEN IT MARINATES
FOR HOW LONG?
TWO, THREE HOURS.
THEN IT GETS PUT
IN THE CRACKER MEAL--DIG IT.
THIS IS OUR,
UH, YELLOW BATTER.
YEAH, THIS IS
OUR GOLDEN BATTER.
GOLDEN BATTER.
USE SOME WATER, FLOUR,
ONE SPOON OF BAKING POWDER.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
SOME EGG...
OKAY, BUDDY,
LET'S SEE IT.
THE TAIL DOESN'T GET
GOLDEN BA--GUESS NOT.
PRETTY QUICK WITH THAT ANSWER.
SO WHAT'S THIS GET SERVED ON?
WE SERVE THIS ON A CUBAN BUN
WITH SOME ONIONS AND KETCHUP.
BREAD COMES FROM
THE CUBAN BAKERY, I TAKE IT?
YES.
AND WE'RE GONNA LEAVE
THE TAIL ON FOR THIS.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE
THE TAIL ON FOR THIS,
ADD SOME ONIONS, KETCHUP,
AND THAT'S OUR MINUTA SANDWICH.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
WOW, THAT'S CRAZY,
BUT IT WORKS.
FISH BY ITSELF IS ON POINT.
THAT MARINADE
REALLY WORKED ON IT.
THE KETCHUP, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEETNESS
OFFSET WITH SOME
OF THE SHARPNESS OF THE ONION--
SO YOU HAVE ALL THESE DIFFERENT
CONTRASTING FLAVORS GOING ON.
NICE JOB. NO WONDER
IT'S SO POPULAR.
IT'S GREAT--
THE TAIL THING'S WEIRD.
PEOPLE EAT IT AT THE END?
YEAH, SOME PEOPLE DO.
TRY IT OUT.
THAT'S GOOD TAIL.
IT'S JUST SO DELICIOUS.
WITH THAT LITTLE TING
OF SPICE.
THEY HAVE A CUBAN TASTE.
EVEN THE SIDES...
GOT SOME HUSH PUPPIES!
THIS IS THE FRENCH FRY
REPLACEMENT.
FROM SCRATCH,
OUT OF THIS CONTRAPTION...
WHAT IN THE TARNATION...
WHEN WE COME BACK.
CIRCA 1580?
ALL RIGHT. WHOLE FISH,
FISH SANDWICH READY!
AT LA CAMARONERA...
(man) BEAUTIFUL.
IN MIAMI'S LITTLE HAVANA...
YOU'VE GOTTA FIGHT THE CROWDS.
THAT'S THE ONE THING.
THERE WE GO.
DAVID GARCIA AND HIS FAMILY...
(man) PAN CON MINUTA.
ARE SERVING FRESH SEAFOOD
CUBAN-STYLE.
(man) MANGO SNAPPER.
EVERYTHING'S FRIED.
IT'S WORKED 36 YEARS.
IT AIN'T BROKE,
DON'T FIX IT.
EXACTLY.
A COUPLE ORDERS
OF GREEN PLANTAINS.
THEY'RE EVEN FRYING
FRUIT AND VEGGIES.
SOME HUSH PUPPIES IN NOW.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THIS IS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
THEY CALL IT,
UH, CARITAS.
FRIJOLE CARITA,
WHICH IS A KIND OF BEAN.
YOU CALL BLACK-EYED BEAN
OR BLACK-EYED PEA?
WE CALL IT
BLACK-EYED BEAN.
THIS IS A BEAN CRACKER.
IT'S GONNA CRACK 'EM ALL UP
INTO THIS BAG DOWN HERE.
LOOK WHAT I DO FOR YOU.
THIS IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY THE PEOPLE THAT INVENTED
THE CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG.
NOTHIN' I LIKE MORE
THAN EXPOSED PULLEYS.
TALK ABOUT GETTIN' A SHIRT TAIL
CAUGHT UP IN--(grumbles)
WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
IN SOME WATER.
THE BLACK EYE
OF THE BEAN...
THE BLACK PART
OF THE BEAN FLOATS
IT FLOATS TO THE TOP.
TAKE ALL THE BLACK EYES,
TO MAKE SURE THEY'RE DRY,
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE 'EM
FOR PROBABLY EIGHT HOURS OR SO.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE'RE TALKIN'
ABOUT--THE BLACK-EYED PEAS
ALL GROUND UP, RECONSTITUTED,
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA GRIND 'EM.
EXACTLY.
GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN, BROTHER.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS UP--
SALT WITH GROUND PEPPER.
START THIS UP.
HEY, YOU WANT ME TO BE
THE GARLIC AND SALT GUY?
YEAH, THAT'LL BE GREAT.
WHEN'S THAT GARLIC
START GOIN' DOWN?
DO THAT NOW, ABOUT TWO
AT A TIME. THERE WE GO.
TEAMWORK.
A LOT OF WORK
JUST TO MAKE A FRITTER.
YEAH.
DIFFERENT THAN A LOT
OF HUSH PUPPIES I'VE SEEN.
NOW WE'LL MIX IT UP.
AND THEN WE FRY IT.
EXACTLY.
HOW MANY COME IN AN ORDER?
TEN.
WILL THEY ROLL OVER
ON THEMSELVES?
THEY'LL ROLL OVER.
YOU CAN HAVE 'EM WITH KETCHUP.
YOU CAN HAVE 'EM
WITH TARTAR SAUCE, SOME LIME.
I LIKE YOUR HERDING TECHNIQUE,
IN THE CORNER FOR YOU. YAH.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT
SOME HUSH PUPPIES.
HOW DO THEY SWELL UP LIKE THAT?
THERE'S NO BAKING SODA
IN 'EM, NO FLOUR.
JUST THE BEAN.
DOES THAT LOOK
LIKE JUST BEAN TO YOU?
THOSE ARE ROCKIN'.
AWESOME.
I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GARLIC IN THERE,
BUT I GET
A REAL DISTINCT FLAVOR.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
THEY HAVE GOT MORE FLAVOR
AND MORE SEASONING TO 'EM--
I DON'T GET STUMPED
ON MANY FOOD ITEMS.
THIS ONE REALLY DOES STUMP ME.
THESE ARE KILLER.
AWESOME.
CHEERS, MAN. NICE JOB.
NO, IT IS REALLY GOOD.
IF I HADN'T
SEEN HIM MAKE IT,
I WOULD NOT HAVE BELIEVED IT
IN A MILLION YEARS.
NOT AT ALL.
IT'S SIMPLE, BUT KIND OF GOES
BACK TO THE ROOTS.
(man speaking Spanish)
CUBAN FOOD IS THE BEST FOOD I'VE
EVER HAD, AND I'M A SPANIARD.
PAN CON MINUTA?
WE WANT SEAFOOD,
WE COME HERE.
EVERY TIME I COME, I-I GOTTA
SQUEEZE INTO SOMEBODY'S PLACE.
I WANT TO GET MY COUNTER SPOT
WITH MY NAME ON THERE.
WE'LL MAKE SURE
WE MARK IT FOR YOU.
I'M COMIN' BACK.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN'
FOR YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'M GONNA PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT TO A RARE.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT
TO A "RAY-ER."
I'VE NEVER HEARD THAT.
YOU'VE GOTTA ADD
THE "ER."
OH, I KNOW.
I--YOU TOOK ME THERE.
WE'LL TAKE IT
TO A "RAY-ER."
"RAY-ER."