HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
BEST TACOS IN TOWN.
(Guy)
THIS TRIP... ALL OVER THE MAP.
IN PHOENIX...
ONE TACO, YOU TRY IT
AND THAT'S IT, YOU'RE HOOKED.
(Guy)
MEXICAN FAVORITES
THIS FAMILY GREW UP WITH.
MMM, GREAT COOK.
LEARNED FROM MY MOTHER!
(Guy)
IN SEATTLE...
ORDER UP, DOLMADES, GYRO.
(Guy)
THE AUTO REPAIR SHOP
TURNED GREEK RESTAURANT...
IT'S REALLY A LOT OF FUN.
TWO BAKLAVAS
AND A BRAKE CHANGE.
(Guy)
WHERE MOM'S STILL DOING
QUALITY CONTROL.
THEN IN SAN FRANCISCO...
THIRD GENERATION
ITALIAN COOKING...
POLENTA SMOTHERED IN CHEESE.
(Guy)
FROM A DUDE STILL USING
HIS GRANDDAD'S RECIPES.
THIS GUY IS A MACHINE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
I'M HERE IN PHOENIX, ARIZONA,
ABOUT FOUR HOURS NORTH OF
THE MEXICAN BORDER.
NOW ASK ANYBODY THAT GOES DOWN
TO MEXICO A BUNCH
WHAT KIND OF FOOD THEY REALLY
LIKE DOWN THERE
AND THEY'RE PROBABLY GONNA SAY
THOSE LITTLE TACOS THAT
YOU BUY ON THE STREET.
SO IN THE '80s,
THE OCHOA FAMILY STARTED SELLING
THOSE LITTLE TACOS
OUT OF A TACO TRUCK.
WELL, FAST-FORWARD
20 YEARS LATER,
AND THE FIVE DAUGHTERS ARE
STILL SELLING THOSE GREAT TACOS
HERE AT LOS TAQUITOS.
THEY'RE LITTLE STREET TACOS.
ONE TACO, YOU TRY AND THAT'S IT,
YOU'RE HOOKED.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST TACOS
IN TOWN.
(Guy)
'CAUSE THEY'RE STILL MADE
MOM'S WAY...
YOU'RE THE MOM?
(Guy)
BY HEAD CHEF VICKIE OCHOA...
AND THE REST OF THE FAMILY.
FIVE SISTERS,
ALL WORKING TOGETHER.
DO YOU GET ALONG?
AND THERE'S A BROTHER?
THERE'S A BROTHER IN THERE.
ARE THOSE ALMOST DONE?
ALMOST.
(Guy)
AND TOGETHER,
THEY'RE CRANKING OUT
MORE THAN 3,000 TACOS A WEEK.
AND THE REST OF
THE FAMILY COOKBOOK.
FLAUTAS, COOKED JUST RIGHT.
THE MENUDO HAS GOT SOME ZIP!
THE CHILE RELLENOS
ARE EXCELLENT.
GREAT SAUCES, GREAT EVERYTHING.
(Guy)
BUT IT'S THOSE LITTLE TACOS...
BIG HANDS AND A LITTLE TACO.
(Guy)
THAT STARTED IT ALL.
THE FRESH INGREDIENTS,
YOU CAN TASTE THE MEAT.
CARNE ASADA, CHICKEN...
(Guy)
OR A SPICED PULLED PORK
CALLED...
CARNITAS.
WE'RE MAKING OUR CARNITAS.
SO THAT'S A PORK SHOULDER,
BOSTON BUTT.
TRIM A LITTLE BIT OF THE FAT
OFF THE TOP.
NOT A LOT.
A LITTLE BIT OF FAT AS FLAVOR.
I THINK THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU THINK THAT'S ENOUGH?
OKAY, NOW WHAT HAPPENS,
PUT SOME SLICES IN IT?
WE LEAVE OUR BONE,
JUST GIVE IT A LITTLE SLICE
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR
TWO CINNAMON STICKS,
GARLIC,
MAKE SURE YOU CUT THE END,
THAT WAY IT COOKS OUT MORE.
SALT.
CONDENSED MILK.
SOME CONDENSED MILK, REALLY?
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT.
SOME COLA.
SOME SODA,
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
WE HAVE OUR OWN RECIPE...
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
JUST TO COVER IT A LITTLE BIT.
PUT IT IN ON OUR STOVE
AND COVER IT...
SO TWO HOURS
UNTIL IT JUST FALLS APART.
AFTER WE TAKE 'EM OUT
WE SHRED 'EM WITH OUR KNIFE.
HOW IS THE FLAVOR SO GREAT
AND THERE'S NO OIL?
THE CONDENSED MILK?
AND THE SODA.
WHO NEEDS IT IN A TACO,
I JUST WANT IT LIKE THAT.
YOU NEED TO TRY THE TACO.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE A TACO.
PUT THIS ON THE GRILL,
THIS IS OUR PORK.
THIS IS KILLER.
GET OUR TORTILLAS,
YOU HAVE TO SPANK 'EM
TO MAKE SURE THEY'RE WELL DONE.
BAD LITTLE TORTILLAS!
TORTILLAS, CARNITAS.
AND A LITTLE CILANTRO?
A LITTLE CILANTRO
AND RED ONION.
AND THEN OUR SALSA,
THERE YOU GO.
MMM.
GOOD?
NO, THEY'RE NOT GOOD...
THEY'RE AWESOME?
I HAVE SOME FAVORITE FOODS
IN MY LIFE,
AND TACOS ARE ONE OF THEM.
THAT'S UP THERE WITH SOME OF
THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
THE SALSA, THE ONIONS,
THE CILANTRO.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE IT
EXACTLY LIKE THAT.
THAT'S THE TASTE OF A TACO.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
IT REMINDS ME OF HOME,
MORE TRADITIONAL.
THEY WAY THAT MOM SERVED IT.
THE SAME RECIPES THAT
YOUR MOM AND DAD WERE USING
THEN?
YES.
(Guy)
FOR JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
JUST TO DIE FOR.
THE CARNE ASADA TORTA,
IT'S AWESOME.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, DELICIOUS SANDWICH.
THE MEAT'S TENDER,
CRISP, COLD LETTUCE,
THE TOASTING ON THE BUN,
I DON'T GO TO
MANY MEXICAN RESTAURANTS
LOOKING FOR A SANDWICH,
BUT I'D ORDER THAT AGAIN
FOR SURE.
SO DELICIOUS.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE FOOD.
(Guy)
AND HOMEMADE SALSAS,
HALF A DOZEN OF THEM.
A LARGE PICO DE GALLO TO GO.
I LOVE THEIR GREEN SAUCE.
THEIR GREEN SAUCE IS FANTASTIC.
THAT'S THE RED SAUCE.
THE HOT SAUCE?
(Guy)
MADE WITH ROASTED RED CHILES.
WHOA, I JUST GOT A NICE HIT
OFF THOSE RIGHT THERE.
AND AN EVEN HOTTER ONE
CALLED "BOMBERO."
BOMBERO IS "FIREMAN" IN SPANISH.
WHAT ARE YOU ENJOYING?
A BOMBERO BURRITO.
SAY THAT FIVE TIMES FAST.
BOMBERO BURRITO,
BOMBERO BURRITO.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE FIRST?
THE BOMBERO SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
OUR TOMATO.
OKAY, JUST A WHOLE TOMATO,
JUST CHUCK IT RIGHT IN?
WHOLE TOMATOES, JUST LIKE THAT,
ONE ONION,
AND THEN WE ADD WATER.
ROAST CHILES.
THOSE ARE HOT.
THEY'RE REALLY HOT.
THAT'S IT, AND LET IT BOIL?
THAT'S IT.
THEY SIT THERE AND STEEP
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR,
LET IT COOL DOWN
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT INTO
THE SALSA.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE WHOLE
MIXTURE INTO THE BLENDER.
AND THEN WE ADD SOME...
A LITTLE CHIPOTLE
WITH ADOBO SAUCE?
YEP,
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER.
COMINO.
OR CUMIN.
A LITTLE GARLIC SALT,
A CLOVE OF GARLIC.
AND KETCHUP.
IT HAS THAT
SWEET AND SPICY FLAVOR.
WE'LL BLEND IT UP.
YOU'RE GONNA THROW THE THROTTLE
ON THAT, AREN'T YA?
DUMP IT IN OUR POT...
AND HOW LONG DOES THAT COOK FOR?
ABOUT 45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR.
WHILE THAT'S GOING ON
ARE WE GONNA COOK THE CHICKEN?
WE'RE GONNA WORK ON OUR
GRILLED CHICKEN.
CUT INTO FAJITA STYLE.
YOU'RE LIKE A SURGEON.
LEARNED SINCE I WAS 14.
WE'LL PUT ALL THIS IN A BOWL.
AND THEN WHAT ARE WE GONNA
PUT ON IT?
SOME OF OUR SEASONING SALT...
A LITTLE CUMIN?
GARLIC POWDER,
AND THEN SOME VINEGAR.
JUST MIX IT UP
AND THEN WE'LL PUT IT
ON OUR GRILL.
GRILL IT UNTIL IT'S GETS
CRISPY BROWN,
AT LEAST TEN MINUTES.
IT'S REALLY SPICY,
YOU'RE GONNA NEED A FIREMAN.
I AM?
IT'S VERY SPICY.
WE'LL GET OUR TORTILLA,
PUT IT ON OUR GRILL.
TAKE OUR TORTILLA,
CHICKEN'S READY.
PICO DE GALLO,
PUT RICE ON HERE,
WRAP IT UP.
AND WHERE'S THE SAUCE GO?
WE'LL GET TO THAT PART.
DON'T RUSH IT, HUH?
WE'LL COME TO OUR SAUCE...
MY MOUTH IS WATERING.
THE BOMBERO SAUCE,
SOME CHEESE...
AND GUY, YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
BOMBERO BURRITO.
CAREFUL, IT'S HOT.
WOW, THERE'S A LITTLE BIT OF
KICK TO THAT,
BUT NOTHING'S TOO OVERPOWERING.
KEEP EATING IT WITHOUT
BEING SPICED UP.
THE CHICKEN'S GOT
A LITTLE CRUNCH
AND A LITTLE CRUST ON IT.
BUT THE SAUCE...
WITH THE KETCHUP.
A LITTLE COOL PICO DE GALLO,
YOU GET...
A LITTLE BIT OF
THE FRESHNESS.
EXCELLENT.
IT'S A HOT, SPICY TASTE,
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S VERY SAVORY,
IT'S GOT LIKE,
A NICE SALTY PUNCH.
GREAT COOK.
LEARNED FROM MY MOTHER.
IF IT WAS MY LAST MEAL
I WOULD COME HERE TO EAT IT,
I SWEAR.
I HAD A MISSION IN LIFE
TO FIND THE BEST TACO
IN THE WORLD,
AND I FOUND IT.
THEY LOVE OUR FOOD.
WHAT'S YOUR BUSIEST DAY?
EVERY DAY.
THAT'S A GOOD WEEK.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
DOLMADES, GYROS, SAGANAKI.
(Guy)
A GREEK JOINT IN SEATTLE...
TASTES ALMOST EXACTLY THE SAME
AS IN GREECE.
(Guy)
WHERE THEY'RE LETTING ME
PLAY WITH MATCHES.
THAT'S A FIRE!
WHEN "TRIPLE D" CRUISES IN TO
SEATTLE,
AND WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
GREEK FOOD,
FIRST THING THAT COMES TO MIND
IS OUR FRIENDS AT
VOULA'S OFFSHORE CAFE.
BUT THEN WE HEAR ABOUT
THIS LITTLE PLACE
ON NORTHWEST 85th THAT
KINDA REMINDS US OF OUR BUDDIES
AT MO GRIDDER'S IN THE BRONX.
SEE, THIS PLACE WAS ONCE
AN AUTO REPAIR SHOP AND DELI,
NOW TURNED RESTAURANT.
SO YOU KNOW I GOTTA CHECK OUT
GEORGIA'S GREEK RESTAURANT
AND DELI.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
THE FOOD IS JUST DELICIOUS.
THERE'S YOUR SAGANAKI.
GYRO SANDWICH, COMING UP.
IT IS LIKE MY MOTHER IS COOKING
BACK THERE.
MOM'S RECIPES ARE AWESOME.
SHE'S THE BEST.
(Guy)
SO GOOD, LAKI KAZAKOS
GAVE HIS MOM GEORGIA
A CORNER OF
HIS AUTO REPAIR SHOP.
THEY WOULD COME UP IN THE FRONT
AND GET STUFF FROM THE DELI.
TWO BAKLAVAS
AND A BRAKE CHANGE.
IT STARTED TAKING OFF.
(Guy)
SO IN '93, LAKI TOOK OUT
THE SERVICE BAYS,
PUT IN A DINING ROOM...
AND STARTED CRANKING OUT
MOM'S RECIPES.
WITH SUPERVISION, OF COURSE.
SO GEORGIA, YOU GIVE HIM
THE SEAL OF APPROVAL.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
WITH MY MOM, ME, AND HIM.
(Guy)
FROM FRESH ROASTED
LEG OF LAMB...
IT'S VERY TENDER, JUICY.
(Guy)
TO STUFFED GRAPE LEAVES
WITH A HOMEMADE YOGURT SAUCE.
AND THIS GREEK CLASSIC.
KEFTEDES.
EXACTLY.
IT'S A MEAT PATTY THAT
WE PUT SAUCE ON.
YEAH, GREEK SALSA,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT.
SO THIS IS A FLAT
GREEK MEATBALL?
NO, IT'S A MEAT PATTY.
YOU CALL YOUR TOMATO SAUCE
SALSA,
AND YOU CALL A MEATBALL --
YOU MAKE IT FLAT, I UNDERSTAND.
GET STARTED WITH OIL,
ITALIAN OLIVE OIL?
(sighs loudly)
WE GOT ONION, TOSS IT IN, BABY.
WE GOT DILL, BAY LEAF.
MINT, A LOT OF MINT USED
IN GREEK FOOD?
A LOT OF OUR COOKING IS FROM
THE NORTHERN PART OF THE GREECE.
THE NORTHERN PART OF
"THE GREECE?"
NORTHEST PART OF THE GREECE.
RIGHT, NORTH IS PART OF
THE GREECE.
(laughing)
A LITTLE BASIL,
IT'S GONNA BE A WILD ONE.
SO THAT WAS OREGANO --
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I'M DOING ALL THIS.
SALT?
OKAY, NOT ITALIAN PARSLEY.
NO.
THIS IS PROBABLY
"SOUTH OF THE GREECE."
ALL THIS IS GONNA SAUTE
TOGETHER.
OKAY, SO NOW THIS IS COOKED.
DICED TOMATOES, FOUR CANS.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
DON'T TOUCH THIS.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
YOU'RE DOING IT RIGHT.
TOMATO PASTE, GARLIC.
A LOT OF IT.
SUGAR.
WOW, GETTIN' DOWN THE SUGAR.
CINNAMON STICKS
AND THE CLOVES.
SO THIS COOKS DOWN
FOR HOW MANY HOURS?
1 1/2 TO 2 HOURS.
WHILE THIS IS COOKING
WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND DO THE PATTIES.
OKAY, WE START OUT WITH
THE 50/50 GROUND MIX OF
BEEF AND LAMB.
"FITTY-FITTY?"
FITTY-FITTY.
BESIDES THE MINT,
IN ITALIAN WE CALL THAT
A MEATBALL.
I JUST...
ONIONS, BREADCRUMBS.
ANY PARTICULAR BREAD?
NO, WHATEVER WE GOT,
THE END PIECES.
THE PARSLEY AND THE MINT
AND THE OREGANO.
(whispering)
HE'S GONNA MAKE ME MIX THIS UP.
BASIL.
OH, MY WRIST!
IT'S BROKE!
LET ME HELP WITH YOU THAT.
GARLIC PUREE.
ADD THE EGGS, SALT, PEPPER,
AND NOW...
GET THE MIX ON?
YEAH.
WOW, LIKE A WORK-OUT VIDEO.
ENOUGH ALREADY, WE'RE DONE!
WE SCOOP AND PLACE THEM DOWN
AND JUST FLATTEN THEM.
GIVE IT A TRY.
OKAY, OVEN 400, 15 MINUTES.
ACTUALLY, 425.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE SALSA ON.
AND YOU JUST LADLE IT ON?
LADLE RIGHT ON TOP.
I TRUST YOU.
BEAUTIFUL, MUST BE THE GREEK
PART OF YOU.
I DON'T HAVE ANY GREEK IN ME.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM BACK IN
THE OVEN FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
BEAUTIFUL,
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF FETA CHEESE ON TOP.
MY MOUTH IS WATERING.
WOW, MAN, IT'S TENDER
LIKE A MEATBALL.
LITTLE BIT OF THE LAMB FLAVOR
IN THERE.
NOW MINT AND OREGANO BOTH
PLAY A BIG ROLE.
I GET A LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS
FROM THE SUGAR,
BUT THEN IT ALL TIES TOGETHER
WHEN YOU BRING THE SALTINESS
OF THE FETA IN.
IT'S LIKE AN ORCHESTRA.
YOU'RE MAKING ME HUNGRY.
(laughing)
THESE MEATBALLS ARE AWESOME.
SEE, I CALL 'EM MEATBALLS TOO.
IT HAS SO MUCH FLAVOR.
EVERYTHING IS REALLY DELICIOUS.
ORDER UP, DOLMADES, GYROS,
AND FRIES.
HE PREPARES EVERYTHING
VERY TRADITIONAL.
THE SAGANAKI RIGHT HERE
TASTES ALMOST EXACTLY THE SAME
AS IN GREECE.
SAGANAKI.
A LITTLE FRIED CHEESE ACTION
GOING RIGHT THERE.
GRAB THE MATCHES.
OPA!
THERE YOU GO,
THAT'S A FIRE!
AND THEN WE SQUEEZE SOME LEMON
ON TOP.
OH, DEFINITELY OFF THE HOOK.
SO YUMMY.
WHEN YOU DON'T GET TO TRAVEL
TO GREECE,
AT LEAST YOU GET TO COME HERE.
I WANT THEM TO FEEL LIKE
THEY WALK INTO A TAVERNA.
(Guy)
A GREEK CAFE SERVING UP
REAL HOME COOKING.
SPANAKOPITA.
SPINACH AND FETA CHEESE
IN A PHYLLO DOUGH,
DELICIOUS.
(Guy)
GREEK SHISH KEBABS,
SOUVLAKI...
AND THIS TRADITIONAL
GREEK FAVORITE.
ROAST LEG OF LAMB SANDWICH.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU, GUYS?
THE LAMB.
THE LAMB, NO QUESTION?
BONELESS LAMB LEG.
WE'RE GONNA STAB IT
THEN WE'RE GONNA FILL
THE HOLES UP WITH GARLIC.
LEMON JUICE,
NEXT WE'RE GONNA DO WINE.
WE'VE GOT GREEK SPICE, THYME,
OREGANO, GARLIC, BASIL,
SALT, PEPPER.
I JUST PAT IT A LITTLE BIT DOWN.
HOW MUCH WATER ARE WE PUTTING
IN THERE?
ABOUT A THIRD...
ABOUT A THIRD OF THE WAY
UP THE MEAT.
WHAT TEMP'S THIS GOING IN?
IT'S GONNA BE AT 450 DEGREES
ABOUT 1 1/2 HOURS.
WOW, COOKING HOT.
IT'S HOT.
YEAH, IT'S HOT.
JUST CONFIRMING.
CUT A PIECE OFF HERE.
OH, LOOK AT THE GARLIC
IN THERE.
LAMB FLAVORED GARLIC.
SO WE'LL GET
OUR PITA BREAD HERE,
PUT OLIVE OIL ON IT,
AND LET THAT COOK.
TZATZIKI.
GETTIN' FREAKY WITH
YOUR TZATZIKI.
EXACTLY...
AND SOME RED ONION,
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY,
FETA CHEESE,
ROMAINE LETTUCE,
WRAPPING PAPER,
TOMATOES,
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THE MEAT IN.
GENEROUS PORTION THERE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF
FETA CHEESE.
MMM, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
SLAMMA-JAMMA, I LOVE THAT LAMBA.
THE PITA'S GOT A LITTLE CRUNCH,
THE TZATZIKI'S NOT OVERPOWERING,
LETTUCE AND TOMATOES,
SOME SWEETNESS OUT OF THAT,
THEN YOU GET THE LAMB
WHICH HAS BIG FLAVOR.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU DON'T SHARE VERY GOOD,
DO YOU?
NO.
I CAN TELL.
THE LAMB IS FRESH.
IT'S KINDA LIKE BACK AT HOME.
IT'S LIKE I'M TAKING
A LITTLE MINI-VACATION.
IT'S REALLY A LOT OF FUN.
EVERY TIME I COME HERE,
I FEEL LIKE I'M PART OF
THE FAMILY.
GREAT TIME, I'M COMING BACK.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY
A FLAMING CHEESE FROM MR. OPA.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
WE'RE HEADING TO SAN FRAN...
I NEVER HAD ANYTHING HERE
I DIDN'T LIKE.
(Guy)
TO PICK UP SOME PICCATA.
YOU JUST GOTTA LOVE SAN FRAN.
I MEAN, ALL THE GREAT
RESTAURANTS THAT ARE OWNED
BY REAL CHARACTERS.
LIKE THIS PLACE, ROCCO'S.
NOW IT'S OWNED BY A DUDE
NAMED DON DIAL,
EVERYBODY CALLS HIM "DOUBLE D,"
SO I THOUGHT IT'D JUST BE
PERFECT THAT HE BE ON
"TRIPLE D."
LET'S GO, PICK IT UP!
DOUBLE D CAN DO PRETTY MUCH
ANYTHING WHEN IT COMES
TO COOKING.
CHICKEN PICCATA.
CLAMS IN WHITE CREAM SAUCE.
ITALIAN SAUSAGE...
IT'S IN MY BLOOD,
I'M THIRD GENERATION.
ITALIAN ON MY MOTHER'S SIDE.
WHO WAS ROCCO?
ROCCO WAS MY GRANDFATHER.
(Guy)
WHO RAN HIS OWN JOINT
FOR 30 YEARS...
NOW DON'S GOING ON 20,
USING SOME OF ROCCO'S
FAVORITE RECIPES.
THE MARINARA SAUCE IS
SECOND TO NONE.
CHICKEN MARSALA,
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
POLENTA SMOTHERED IN CHEESE.
(Guy)
TOPPED WITH GRANDPA'S
BOLOGNESE,
DOUBLE D'S MAKING FRESH
EVERY DAY.
WE COOK ROAST BEEF
AND ROAST PORK ON OUR MENU
SO IT'S ALREADY ROASTED IN
THE WINE, THE GARLIC,
THE ROSEMARY.
NOW WE PUT OUR CELERY,
RED AND WHITE ONION,
ITALIAN SAUSAGE -- MILD.
MILD, WHY?
'CAUSE WE CAN ADD SPICES.
ONCE IT'S HOT,
WE CAN'T TAKE IT OUT.
WHO WOULD'VE KNOWN.
ITALIAN PARSLEY,
SLICED MUSHROOMS,
FRESH BASIL.
STEMS OF ROSEMARY.
IF YOU TAKE THOSE STEMS OF
THE BASIL,
SOAK THEM IN SOME
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
AND THEN USE THAT
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL
TO MAKE YOUR SALAD DRESSING.
BOOM, IT'LL KILL YA.
SO WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS UP
AND PUT IT IN A CUISINART.
IF YOU'RE IN A HURRY,
WHICH I ALWAYS AM,
DO A LITTLE ROCK-N-ROLL.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE CHOKING IT.
GIVE ME BACK THE STOCK!
SEE?
SO NOW WHAT TAKES PLACE?
1 CUP OF GARLIC
INTO OLIVE OIL.
GROUND CHUCK,
THE GARLIC IS GOING IN THE MEAT
SO IT WON'T BURN.
NOW WE PUT OUR GROUND PORK
AND GROUND BEEF.
SAME PROCESS HERE.
WHO TAUGHT YOU THIS METHOD?
MY UNCLE, ROCCO'S SON IS LOU.
SO YOUR MOM'S BROTHER LOU
TAUGHT YOU THIS?
CORRECT.
WE'RE ADDING A LOT OF WINE
TO THAT.
REALLY?
A LOT OF WINE.
ALL THREE?
HALF OF THAT ONE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT MUCH
RED WINE GO IN A BOLOGNESE.
THEN WE ADD CRUSHED TOMATOES.
MIX IT UP
AND I'M GONNA ADD SOME WATER.
THAT'S THE SALT,
THAT'S THE SUGAR.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
DRY OREGANO, DRY BASIL,
A POUND OF BUTTER.
THAT IS CRAZY.
HOW LONG'S THIS BAD BOY
GONNA COOK DOWN?
FOUR HOURS.
SO YOU MAKE YOUR OWN POLENTA?
WE MAKE OUR OWN POLENTA.
WHAT DO YOU PUT IN IT?
I BOIL HOMEMADE CHICKEN BROTH,
THEN WE POUR THE POLENTA IN,
KEEP MOVING.
A CUBE OF BUTTER
BECAUSE WE'RE MAKING A LOT.
HOW MUCH ARE WE MAKING?
THREE LOAVES.
PARMESAN CHEESE,
FRESH PARSLEY.
SO THEN WE PUT IT IN HERE,
LET THAT CHILL.
THAT CHILLS OVERNIGHT.
LOG-O-POLENTA.
POP IT OUT.
NOT MY FIRST RODEO.
TAKE A SLICE
THEN WE PUT IT ON THE GRILL.
THEN COVER IT
TO STEAM IT A LITTLE BIT.
YOU PUT THE VEGETABLES IN THERE.
NOW FRESH GARLIC AND OIL.
AND YOU PUT BUTTER,
VEGETABLES.
THIS PAN HERE,
ONLY FOR VEGETABLES,
NEVER TOUCHES THE WATER.
I'VE SEASONED IT,
I BLACKENED IT,
THIS PAN'S BEEN HERE FOR
16 YEARS.
FRESH BASIL, MONTEREY JACK.
THIS IS READY TO GO,
PLATE THE POLENTA,
VEGETABLES SECOND,
BOLOGNESE.
A LITTLE PARMESAN CHEESE
AND FRESH BASIL.
MMM, BOY, THAT'S NICE.
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT DEEPER
THAN THE AVERAGE BOLOGNESE.
IT'S A LOT SWEETER
THAN I ANTICIPATED.
BUT I THINK THE ROASTED MEAT...
THAT'S THE BEST FLAVOR
FROM IT.
IT'S GOT SOME REAL COMPLEXITY,
THAT'S KILLER.
GREAT POLENTA, TOO.
IS THE REST OF THE FOOD
GONNA BE LIKE THIS?
YOU'RE GONNA EAT TODAY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
OUTSTANDING.
THE LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
DON IS THE SHOW.
YOU GOTTA WATCH THIS.
THIS GUY IS A MACHINE.
I LIKE TO SIT BY THE KITCHEN
AND WATCH.
I HAVE HIGH ENERGY.
IT'S VERY ENTERTAINING.
(Guy)
'CAUSE THIS GUY IS COOKIN'.
LET'S GO, PICK IT UP!
EGGPLANT SANDWICH,
LOT OF FLAVOR, NICE AND JUICY.
THE FRITTATA'S ARE REALLY GOOD.
I'VE HAD ALMOST EVERYTHING,
CHICKEN PICCATA.
I THINK WE SHOULD MAKE SOME
CHICKEN PICCATA
BECAUSE I AM A PICCATA
AFICIONADO.
OKAY, EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
THE INDUSTRIAL CAN SIZE.
FRESH CHICKEN BREASTS.
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU SLICED
THESE BREASTS IN HALF...
NOT POUNDED THEM.
YOU GOT IT.
YOU DREDGE THESE IN
REGULAR ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
EXACTLY.
WE PUT THE CHICKEN BREAST IN,
JUST MAKE SURE...
WHOA, WHOA, WHAT IS THAT THERE,
FREDDY KRUEGER?
THAT'S MY FORK,
IT'S AN EXTENSION OF MY HAND.
THEN WE DRAIN THE OIL
OFF THE CHICKEN,
CONTINUE MOTION OF
WASHING THE PAN.
I HAVE A NEW RESPECT
FOR THE BARBECUE FORK.
FLOUR ON TOP OF THE CHICKEN
SO IT WON'T BROWN.
SHAKING AS YOU POUR
THE WINE IN.
NOW WE ADD CHICKEN BROTH.
IT'S STARTING TO REDUCE,
STARTING TO TIGHTEN UP.
BLACK PEPPER, PARSLEY,
BUTTER,
CAPERS, VERY LITTLE SALT.
FRESH SQUEEZED HALF LEMON,
RIND DOWN.
SEEDS AND ALL?
SEEDS AND ALL.
THAT'S LIKE A PICCATA CROUTON.
USE THE LEMON,
THE LEMON'S IN THERE.
YOU WANT A THICK SAUCE.
YOU SHOULD TASTE THE WINE
A LITTLE STRONG RIGHT NOW.
IT IS.
IT'LL COME DOWN.
IT'S OVERPOWERING WITH
THE LEMON?
DO YOU LIKE YOUR LEMON?
GET A LOAD OF THIS GUY.
OR DO YOU TAKE THE LEMON
OUT OF YOUR ICED TEA?
HE DOES NOT STOP TALKING.
YOU SAID I HAD TOO MUCH LEMON.
I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
I MEAN, I'M GETTING MY VITAMIN C
INTAKE FOR THE REST OF THE YEAR.
THIS GOES LIKE THIS
FOR OUR GARNISH.
OH, MORE LEMON!
AND THERE IT IS.
MMM, THE CHICKEN REALLY
TOOK THAT SAUCE UP NICE.
IT'S SUPER TENDER,
RIGHT AMOUNT OF CAPERS.
A LITTLE LEMONY.
I TOLD YOU IT WAS LEMONY.
IT'S AWESOME, DUDE.
THE TASTE IS OUTSTANDING,
VERY GOOD.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING HERE
I DIDN'T LIKE.
THE FOOD SPEAKS FOR ITSELF.
(Guy)
AND IN SAN FRANCISCO,
A LOT OF IT'S TALKING SEAFOOD.
I CAN MAKE SOME HAPPY PEOPLE
WITH THIS.
(Guy)
YEAH, HAPPY AS CLAMS...
AND LINGUINI,
WHEN WE COME BACK.
(Guy)
AT ROCCO'S IN SAN FRANCISCO
DON DIAL'S DOING
WHAT HIS GRANDPA ROCCO DID...
COOKING UP THE ITALIAN
CLASSICS.
THE FOOD IS LOCAL,
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S DONE VERY WELL,
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
IN SAN FRANCISCO
YOU GET ALL THIS FRESH SEAFOOD.
(Guy)
AND HERE, IT'S ITALIAN STYLE,
OVER PASTA.
CALAMARI OVER LINGUINI,
BUTTERFLIED PRAWNS OVER
A BED OF LINGUINI.
IT'S LINGUINI WITH CLAMS
AND WHITE SAUCE.
(Guy)
A ROCCO'S FAN FAVORITE.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE CLAMS.
CLAMS WITH LINGUINI
IN WHITE SAUCE.
CANNED CLAMS?
THEY'RE CHOPPED
BABY WHOLE CLAMS.
GIMME THE TOUR, BROTHER.
GARLIC, BABY WHOLE CLAMS,
FRESH CLAMS.
SO THE BABY WHOLES WITH
THE JUICE IS THE BIG FLAVOR,
THESE ARE KINDA LIKE THE SHOW.
PEOPLE SAY, "I LIKE IT WHEN
I GO TO A PLACE
AND ITS' ALL CLAM SHELLS."
BUT IF YOU TRY TO GET
THAT MANY CLAMS WITH SHELLS,
YOU'D HAVE A WHOLE
STEAMER BASKET.
NOW WE ADD SOME WHITE WINE,
HALF AND HALF,
AND WE ADD SOME BUTTER.
IT'S BETTER WITH BUTTER.
PEPPER, BASIL.
WE LET THIS BAD BOY REDUCE.
A GREAT TECHNIQUE ON THE CLAMS,
BEFORE IT'S COOKED,
YOU TAP IT ON THE SHELL,
IT SHOULD CLOSE UP A LITTLE BIT.
'CAUSE IT'S STILL ALIVE.
RIGHT, THAT'S TRUE.
BUT THEN WHEN YOU DO COOK
THE CLAMS, IF THE CLAM SHELL
DOESN'T OPEN UP,
WELL, THEN YOU PROBABLY
SHOULDN'T EAT THAT ONE.
AND THEY'RE POPPING OPEN
AS WE SPEAK.
THEY ARE, IT'S LIKE,
TAKE A LOOK AT ME!
THEY'RE ON CUE.
SO I PUT THE PASTA.
PRE-COOKED,
SHOCKED IN COLD WATER?
RIGHT.
GET ALL THAT WATER OUT,
WE DON'T WANT TO MAKE CLAM SOUP.
WE'RE MAKING LINGUINI WITH
CLAMS.
CLAMS GO AROUND THE PLATE
FOR DECORATION.
OUR SAUCE RIGHT ON TOP.
PARMESAN CHEESE,
A LITTLE PARSLEY ON IT.
LOOK AT THE RATIO OF CLAMS
TO PASTA.
NICE, GOOD SEAFOOD FLAVOR
AND THE CLAMS ARE TENDER.
I WILL FOR SURE STEAL
THAT RECIPE.
YOU CAN HAVE IT.
I CAN MAKE SOME HAPPY PEOPLE
WITH THIS.
SHOVEL THAT IN MY POCKET.
A LOT OF FRESH BASIL,
HEAVY CREAM, BUTTER,
JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
SOME OF THE BEST LINGUINI CLAMS,
I'M TELLIN' YA.
I LOVE IT, I NEVER LEAVE HUNGRY.
ROCCO'S IS AWESOME.
IT'S WONDERFUL,
GREAT PLACE TO GO.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA COME HERE
TO BE SEEN,
YOU'RE GONNA COME HERE TO EAT
AND EAT GOOD.
THE WORLD NEEDS TO TRY THIS,
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE WORLD NEEDS TO TRY THIS?
THIS IS WHERE I'M AT,
THIS IS WHERE I BELONG,
AND I COULDN'T BE ANYWHERE ELSE.
AWESOME, BRO.
RIGHT ON, MAN,
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED FOR SOME
MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
AND HOMINY,
AND IT'S MADE WITH...
(Guy)
HOMINY-HOMINY?
HOMINY-HOMINY!
Closed Captioning Provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC