I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
YOU GOTTA GET UNDER THERE.
(Guy)
A BURGER, A BOWL, AND A SLICE
IN DALLAS...
I NEED THIS TODAY.
(Guy)
WHERE A COUPLE
OF CULINARY SCHOOL GRADS...
I GOT A BUFFALO BURGER
COMIN' UP.
(Guy)
ARE DOIN' BURGERS
THEY'RE PROUD TO CALL TWISTED.
CHIPOTLE GUACAMOLE.
REALLY INCREDIBLE.
(Guy)
IN SEATTLE...
CHILI VERDE.
(Guy)
WHEN THE CHILI
JUST KEEPS ON COMIN',
AND YOU CAN GET IT
ON JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
MMM, THAT'S THE WAY
TO MAC IT OUT RIGHT THERE.
IN ARIZONA...
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL, I WON'T
EAT PIZZA ANYWHERE ELSE.
(Guy)
A FAMILY PIZZA JOINT...
IT'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH MY GRANDMOTHER'S COOKING.
(Guy)
WHERE THEY'RE STILL
CRANKIN' OUT...
A LITTLE FETA CHEESE, PLEASE.
(Guy)
WHAT THEIR GRANDPARENTS DID.
CHICKEN PESTO LASAGNA
BUT MADE WITH SPAGHETTI.
MMM, DELICIOUS, NICE JOB.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
♪
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE OUR OWN
LANGUAGE HERE ON TRIPLE D.
WE LIKE TO SAY
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
WE LIKE IT A LITTLE CRAZY,
A LITTLE WILD,
A LITTLE OFF THE HOOK,
MAYBE A LITTLE TWISTED.
SO WE FOUND A JOINT
HERE IN EAST DALLAS CALLED
TWISTED ROOT BURGER COMPANY.
WELL, THEY'RE NOW SPEAKIN'
TRIPLE D LANGUAGE,
AND WE JUST GOTTA
CHECK 'EM OUT.
WILE E. COYOTE,
YOUR FOOD'S READY, ENJOY IT.
THANK YOU.
WHEN YOU ORDER YOUR BURGER,
THEY GIVE YOU A LITTLE CARD.
IT HAS A NAME ON IT,
YOU KNOW, YOU GET CALLED...
QUICK DRAW MCGRAW.
KING OF NOTTINGHAM.
(Guy)
FOLKS WILL ANSWER
TO JUST ABOUT ANY NAME.
I WAS MISTER TAMBOURINE MAN.
(Guy)
BECAUSE WHEN THEY DO...
PAMELA ANDERSON,
THIS IS YOU RIGHT HERE.
(Guy)
LOOK WHAT THEY GET.
IT'S REALLY INCREDIBLE,
HONESTLY.
CHIPOTLE, GUACAMOLE, CHEDDAR,
BLUE CHEESE, JALAPENO BURGER.
GREEN CHILI, GUACAMOLE,
AND PEPPER JACK.
(Guy)
ALL SERVED UP
MEDIUM PIZZA.
(Guy)
BY A COUPLE OF CLASSICALLY
TRAINED CHEFS, QUINCY HART...
THREE HAMS AND A CHILI.
(Guy)
AND JASON BOSO.
WE MET IN CULINARY SCHOOL,
OUR FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL.
ALL THROUGH SCHOOL,
WE TALKED ABOUT RESTAURANTS...
(Guy)
AND DOING ONE THEIR WAY.
CHIPOTLE, GUACAMOLE.
(Guy)
NOT FINE DINING...
VENISON UP.
(Guy)
FINE BURGERS.
ABOUT SIX, SEVEN YEARS LATER,
WE SAID,
"LET'S GET THIS TOGETHER
AND DO THIS," AND HERE WE ARE.
(Guy)
PUTTIN' THEIR OWN TWIST
ON MORE THAN 2,000 BURGERS
A WEEK.
FRESH AND LOCAL INGREDIENTS,
AND WE'RE OFFERING
A GREAT QUALITY PRODUCT.
(Guy)
STARTIN' WITH THE BEEF.
TWO MORE BURGERS.
(Guy)
EVEN USING TWO DIFFERENT
MEAT TO FAT RATIOS.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF 81/19
AND 73/27.
SO WE'RE GETTING OURSELVES
A 77/23.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU SAID ONE'S TOO FATTY,
ONE'S TOO LEAN.
I'M JUST GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE MY OWN BLEND.
EXACTLY.
FAT MAN, HOW MUCH PEPPER?
NOT MUCH, A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF BREAD CRUMBS.
YOU'RE MAKIN' MEATBALLS?
OUR REASON FOR DOING
THE BREAD CRUMBS
IS TO BASICALLY SEAL IN
THE FLAVOR AND THE JUICES.
AND AS OPPOSED TO THAT FAT
MELTING OUT OF THERE,
IT'S GONNA SUCK UP
INTO THAT DRY BREAD CRUMB
AND IT'S GONNA STAY THERE.
CORRECT.
WHAT'S THE AVERAGE SIZE
BURGER HERE?
HALF POUND,
THERE'S NO KIDS BURGERS HERE.
SO YOU MEASURE 'EM OUT
AHEAD OF TIME?
I CAN PRETTY MUCH EYEBALL IT.
WELL, GIVING AWAY THE FARM
ON THAT ONE, QUINCE.
WHAT DID I DO, GUY?
ABOUT 8.4.
CAN WE HAND-FORM THIS?
NO, WE GOT A PATTY MACHINE
THAT SOME GREAT MIND
PUT TOGETHER FOR US.
I SEE YOU'RE ANGRY WITH IT.
YES, SIR.
YOU USED TO DO THIS TOO,
HUH, GUY?
UH-HUH, I USED TO GET IN TROUBLE
IN THE KITCHEN ALSO.
OKAY, THAT'S IT.
I LIKE THE VARIETY OF OPTIONS
OF TOPPINGS.
JUST PICK THE FLAVORS
THAT YOU WANT.
BLUE CHEESE, JALAPENO UP.
A REGULAR BURGER
WITH BLUE CHEESE.
I GOT THE WESTERN BURGER.
WESTERN.
THE WESTERN IS ALWAYS
WHAT I GET, VERY SPICY.
GIVE ME A WESTERN, BROTHER.
IT'S A BIG BURGER.
GIDDY UP.
I LIKE THE LITTLE CRUNCH
YOU GET FROM THE FLAT TOP.
A LITTLE PEPPER JACK CHEESE
ON THAT, SOME BACON.
A LITTLE SQUIRT-SQUIRT.
LITTLE SQUIRT-SQUIRT.
THE STEAM REALLY MELTS IT
FROM THE TOP.
YES, IT DOES.
LOOK AT THAT, GET AFTER THEM.
COME HERE, BACON,
SOME ONION STRINGS ON THAT.
BUILD A LITTLE NEST
FOR THOSE JALAPENOS.
THERE YOU GO.
AND SOME OF MY GRANDDAD'S
BARBECUE SAUCE.
I NEED THIS TODAY.
MAN, THAT'S LIKE THE
EVERLASTING BURGER STOPPER
RIGHT THERE, 900 FLAVORS.
SPICY, SWEET, CRUNCHY, SALTY.
NO QUESTION,
THAT BARBECUE SAUCE IS IT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT,
THE ONION SLICE IS NICE TOUCH.
THAT'S A CHAMPIONSHIP BURGER
RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S A BURGER DONE RIGHT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
GREAT BURGER?
EXCELLENT.
YES, AND ALL THE
OTHER GOODIES WITH IT.
CUTTIN' OUR OWN ONIONS,
CUTTIN' OUR OWN POTATOES.
SWEET POTATOES GOING DOWN.
(Guy)
EVEN SPICED
AND DEEP-FRIED PICKLES.
SPICY PICKLES.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT TO IT,
A LITTLE BIT OF VINEGAR TO IT,
IT'S A GREAT PICKLE.
HOMEMADE KETCHUP.
NO, SERIOUSLY?
(Guy)
WITH ANCHO AND CHIPOTLE PASTE,
SUGAR, CAYENNE PEPPER,
AND SOMETHING THEY'RE KEEPIN'
TO THEMSELVES.
I'VE NEVER HAD
ANY KETCHUP LIKE THIS BEFORE.
REGULAR KETCHUP DOESN'T STAND
A CHANCE WITH IT.
THEY CAN GET
THE REGULAR STUFF TOO.
BUT YOU HAVE
THE TWISTED VERSION OF IT?
WE'VE GOT THE TWISTED VERSION.
OF JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
CHIPOTLE RANCH HOT DOG
COMING OUT.
CINNAMON PECAN ROOT BEER.
AND IT'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT THAN ANYTHING
YOU'VE EVER TRIED BEFORE.
YOU'RE DEFINITELY
AT A DIFFERENT PLACE HERE
THAN YOU'VE EVER
BEEN TO BEFORE.
ORDER UP, JASON.
THE OTHER BURGER PLACES,
IT'S YOUR STANDARD HAMBURGER.
(Guy)
BUT HERE
THE STANDARD IS TWISTED.
BLUE CHEESE, JALAPENO.
(Guy)
AND TWISTED SOME MORE.
I GOT A BUFFALO BURGER
COMIN' UP.
BUFFALO MEAT.
(Guy)
BLUE CHEESE AND JALAPENOS.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL,
VERY JUICY.
I CAN'T STOP THE BUFFALO
FROM FLYIN' OUT THE DOOR.
THERE'S YOU ANOTHER
NAKED BUFFALO.
(Guy)
AND HERE'S ONE
YOU DON'T SEE A LOT.
VENISON.
OOH, HOW IS IT?
EXCELLENT.
WHAT DO WE GOT?
SOME VENISON,
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE BIT MORE
THAN WE HAD IN THE ANGUS.
ON OUR ANGUS 77/23...
AND SOME PEPPER
AND SOME BREAD CRUMBS.
NOT AS A FILLER,
AS A RETAINER OF MOISTURE.
NOT LIKE MEATLOAF, RIGHT?
YEAH.
WE MIX THIS AND THE BUFFALO
BY HAND EVERY DAY.
SO IF YOU MIXED THE BUFFALO
AND THE VENISON,
YOU COULD HAVE A BUFFISON?
THAT'S A GOOD ONE, GUY.
MY GOD, HONEY, DID YOU SEE HIM
RIDIN' THAT BUFFISON
DOWN THE STREET?
IT'S 6 OUNCES THIS TIME.
YOU GO FIRST, WHOEVER IS
CLOSEST WITHOUT GOING OVER.
WHOA!
OKAY, OKAY, GOOD,
THERE'S ONE...
HEY, WHAT CAN I SAY,
THE MAN'S A WINNER.
NOW CAN I PRESS ONE OUT,
READY TO FIRE.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
BEAUTIFUL, NOW WHAT DO
WE SERVE THESE WITH?
SWISS, PEPPERCORN RANCH,
AND BACON.
IS THAT GOOD WITH YOU?
YEAH, LET'S GO,
FEEL THE PAIN!
SWISS CHEESE ON THAT ONE.
YOU GOTTA GET UNDER THERE.
ALL RIGHT, LOOKS GOOD,
THROW SOME BACON ON THAT,
GOOD CRISPY BACON,
AND SOME PEPPERCORN RANCH.
LOOK AT THAT, THAT'S A
GOURMET BURGER RIGHT THERE.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
I WOULD COME BACK
FOR THAT BURGER.
WELL, THANK YOU, MAN.
THAT'S THE GO-TO BURGER
FOR ME.
THE BACON'S GREAT,
THE PEPPERCORN RANCH
IS ON POINT,
BUT THE TEXTURE AND THE FLAVOR
OF VENISON,
THAT'S MY BURGER.
APPRECIATE IT, BROTHER.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF, MAN,
GREAT JOB.
APPRECIATE IT.
THAT'S PROBABLY THE BEST PIECE
OF VENISON I EVER HAD,
AND IT'S IN A BURGER.
IT'S THE BEST BURGER
AROUND HERE TOTALLY.
IT'S SO AWESOME,
THEY HAVE THE BEST BURGERS.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE
WITH A GOOD SENSE OF HUMOR.
IT ALWAYS SOUNDS LIKE
A LITTLE PARTY.
DO YOU GUYS PARTY HERE?
I ALWAYS WANTED TO SAY THIS --
ROUND OF BEERS ON ME!
(yelling)
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
TEXAS RED.
(Guy)
WE'RE GOING TO THE NORTHWEST...
BEST CHILI IN TOWN BY FAR.
(Guy)
FOR A TASTE OF THE SOUTHWEST.
CHILI VERDE.
(Guy)
AND A WHOLE LOT MORE.
THAT'S THE WAY
TO MAC IT OUT RIGHT THERE,
MMM, EXCELLENT!
I'M HERE IN SEATTLE
WHERE MOST PEOPLE
THINK ABOUT GREAT COFFEE
AND THAT CRAZY FISH MARKET.
BUT ME, I THINK ABOUT
SEATTLE'S LIKE A CHILI-VILLE.
NOW I WENT TO
MIKE'S CHILI PARLOR
AND HAD A BLAST,
BUT I'M IN SEARCH
OF ANOTHER CHILI HAVEN.
SO I'M HERE AT SLIM'S
LAST CHANCE CHILI SHACK
AND WATERING HOLE
WHERE I HEAR
THE SMOKED PORK CHILI VERDE
IS OFF THE CHAIN.
CHILI VERDE.
THE PORK IS GREAT,
THE GREEN SAUCE
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
IT HAS A LOT OF TASTE TO IT.
(Guy)
A SOUTHWESTERN FAVORITE
CRANKED OUT
BY A NORTHWESTERN DUDE.
MIKE LUCAS SPENT
ALMOST THREE DECADES
WORKING IN ALL KINDS
OF RESTAURANTS
BEFORE HE AND HIS WIFE CELESTE
OPENED THIS JOINT.
HEY, KNUCKLEHEADS.
AND I KNEW WE WANTED
TO DO HIM A ROADHOUSE,
A JUKE JOINT KINDA OF PLACE.
CHILI JUST SEEMED
TO BE THE ANSWER.
(Guy)
BUT IT WAS
A MULTIPLE CHOICE QUESTION.
CHILI VERDE.
(Guy)
SO HE'S DOING
THE SOUTHWESTERN STYLE.
TEXAS RED.
(Guy)
AND THE CLASSIC...
BRISKET AND BEANS.
(Guy)
AND SOME MORE.
THAT TURKEY WHITE BEAN CHILI.
REALLY.
UH-HUH.
(Guy)
AND HE'LL PUT ANY OF 'EM
ON HOMEMADE JALAPENO
MAC AND CHEESE,
BUT THE FAN FAVORITE
IS THE SOUTHWESTERN GREEN.
BEST CHILI IN TOWN BY FAR.
WE'RE GONNA START THIS.
START WITH KOSHER SALT,
TURBINADO SUGAR.
THE TURBINADO DOESN'T BURN
ON YOU.
PAPRIKA AND DARK CHILI POWDER,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
ONION POWDER, BLACK PEPPER.
GET IT STIRRED UP
AND THEN WE GRIND IT
IN A COFFEE GRINDER TO GO.
SUPER FINE.
MMM, SUPER TASTY.
PORK BUTT OVER HERE,
BUTTERFLY THIS.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA
GIVE THIS SOME RUB.
YOU REALLY GET
INTO EVERY NOOK AND CRANNY.
FLIP THAT OVER,
GET THIS SIDE.
SO FOUR HOURS THIS IS
GONNA GO DOWN IN THE SMOKER
WITH APPLE AND HICKORY.
LOOK AT THAT.
LET'S GET THIS CUBED UP
READY TO GO IN.
THE BARK ON THAT'S A KILLER.
YOU WANNA START WORKIN'
ON OUR CHILI VERDE SAUCE?
ABSOLUTELY, YEAH.
KINDA THROW A CHAR ON 'EM.
SO WE LOAD THOSE UP,
SEAL IT OFF,
LET 'EM SWEAT THEMSELVES.
THOSE ARE LOOKIN' PRIME TIME.
AND YOU WANT THE MAJORITY
OF THE SEEDS OUT?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR.
WE'RE GONNA BLANCH OFF
SOME FRESH TOMATILLOS?
BOIL 'EM AND STRAIN 'EM?
TOMATILLOS IN FIRST,
HANDFUL OF PEPPERS.
WE'RE DOING
THE REAL DEAL HOLYFIELD.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THEN ON IN THERE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH THE PORK,
HIT IT WITH SOME SPICES,
AND THAT'S GONNA BE
GREEN CHILI VERDE
WITH SMOKED PORK?
JUST ABOUT,
A LITTLE MORE TO IT.
AND ALL IN OLIVE OIL,
ONIONS, CHOPPED GARLIC,
JALAPENOS, SERRANOS.
THEN THE PADDLE.
YOU EVER SING
"ROW, ROW, ROW YOUR VEGGIES?"
NO, NEVER.
NEITHER WOULD I.
SCOOP THIS OUT, WE'RE GONNA
BROWN OUR PORK IN HERE.
PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON ALL OF THAT.
DEGLAZE THAT
WITH A LITTLE CHICKEN BROTH.
GET ALL THAT AWESOME STUFF
OFF THE BOTTOM,
ALL THAT GREAT FLAVOR.
WE'LL ADD BACK IN
OUR ONIONS, PEPPERS MIX,
AND ADD IN THAT GREEN SAUCE.
NOW FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
THIS WOULD BE GOOD ENOUGH
RIGHT HERE THE WAY IT IS.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
BUT YOU GOTTA SEE THE ARSENAL
OF FLAVOR BEHIND US.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
A LITTLE SEASONING SALT,
YOU MAKE IT YOURSELF?
ABSOLUTELY, YEAH.
THERE YOU GO.
MEXICAN OREGANO, A LITTLE CUMIN,
BLACK PEPPER, CORIANDER.
YOU GOT IT, GIVE IT A STIR.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'VE GOTTA
ADD A QUICK MASA ROUX TO THAT,
CANOLA OLIVE OIL BLEND,
THAT CORN MASA FLOUR.
OKAY, THAT THEY MAKE
TORTILLAS OUT OF, LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH, STIR IT RIGHT IN.
IT TIGHTENS IT UP AND IT
GIVES IT KIND OF A NICE
LITTLE TORTILLA FLAVOR.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT.
OKAY, SO TURN THE HEAT DOWN,
LET IT GO LOW AND SLOW
FOR 1 1/2 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE CILANTRO
AND THEN WE'RE READY TO EAT.
MMM, IT'S AS GOOD
AS YOU'LL FIND,
NOT OVERLY SALTY.
JUST BECAUSE PEOPLE SEE
IT'S GREEN, I THINK THEY THINK
IT'S GONNA BE HOT
WHEN YOU SAY CHILI, IT'S NOT.
AND THE KILLER APP
IS PILIN' IT ON
THE JALAPENO MAC AND CHEESE.
ALL RIGHT, EXCELLENT,
THAT'S THE WAY
TO MAC IT OUT RIGHT THERE.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPER HEAT.
THEN YOU GET SOME OF THE
SMOKINESS OF THE PORK BUTT,
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH
FROM THE TOPPING.
PUTTIN' THESE TWO TOGETHER,
THAT'S THE WAY I WOULD
ROCK IT RIGHT THERE, BRO.
THE MOST COMFORTING, WARMING,
WONDERFUL DISH IN THE WORLD.
JUST REAL GOOD STUFF,
ONE OF MY STAPLES.
NOW YOU CAN HAVE
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
SEVERAL WAYS TO TOP IT, YEAH.
I GET TORTILLA STRIPS,
SO IT'S KINDA LIKE NACHOS
AT THE SAME TIME.
SOUR CREAM, CHEESE,
FRESH TOMATOES ON THERE TOO.
YOU CAN ORDER IT
THE WAY YOU WANT,
AND THEY BRING IT
HOW YOU WANT IT.
YEP.
(Guy)
AND WHATEVER YOU WANT IT
ON TOP OF.
CHILI CHEESE FRIES.
CHEDDAR GRITS.
TRIPLE D WORTHY
CHILI CHEESE BURGER,
THERE'S NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT.
(Guy)
BUT FOR THE CHILI PURIST,
IT'S A BASIC BOWL OF BASIC RED.
SAUCE AND MEAT,
THAT'S WHAT CHILI IS.
WHAT'S THE FIRST STEP?
OIL, ADD OUR ONIONS.
TEAMWORK.
RED BELL PEPPERS,
GREEN BELL PEPPERS, JALAPENOS,
A COUPLE OF 'EM.
COUPLE OF 'EM.
FRESH GARLIC, STIR THAT UP,
GET A LITTLE SWEAT ON 'EM.
THEY'RE A LITTLE CARAMELIZED,
THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
I'M GONNA PULL THESE OUT,
GET THE MEAT AND ADD THAT IN.
ONCE WE GET THIS BROWNED
WE'LL ADD OUR VEGGIES INTO IT.
WE'RE MAKIN' A MESS OF 'EM,
MESS IS GOOD.
YEAH.
ADD IN SOME
STRAIGHT KOSHER SALT.
THANK GOODNESS, I HAVE BEEN...
WHOA, WHOA, EASY.
OH, THIS ISN'T FOR ME?
NO, THIS IS...
WELL, YOU STIR THEN,
FIVE QUARTS OF BEER.
CHILI POWDER, PAPRIKA,
GEPHARDT'S CHILI POWDER.
THIS ONE?
ANCHO CHILI POWDER,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
ONION POWDER, CUMIN,
SOME SEASONED SALT,
AND ACHIOTE, IS IT?
I DON'T WANT THAT PASTE.
THIS IS A PASTE
THAT YOU CAN BUY
IN A LOT OF LATINO MARKETS.
THIS IS GONNA GIVE
SOME REALLY DYNAMITE COLOR
TO THIS WHOLE MESS.
NOW I'VE GOT VERY LITTLE
TOMATO IN THIS,
BUT HERE IT IS...
THAT'S IT?
AND THAT'S KETCHUP.
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR
COMING IN FROM THAT.
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET,
ADD A LITTLE MORE BEER
INTO THAT.
AND THAT WILL TAKE US
TO TEXAS RED CHILI?
JUST ABOUT.
HE ALWAYS HAS
JUST THAT EXTRA LITTLE PIECE.
AS THIS COOKS DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
GET THAT RED CHILI OIL
AND MAKE SOME MASA ROUX,
SPREAD IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
YOU WANT ME TO TASTE THAT
A WHOLE BUNCH OF TIMES?
PROBABLY WAIT ABOUT 1 1/2 HOURS
'TIL IT'S READY TO GO.
TEXAS RED.
MMM, THIS IS SO GOOD.
IF SOMEBODY WANTS GOOD
TEXAS-TYPE CHILI,
MMM, THIS IS IT.
I MEAN, THIS HAS
GOT IT GOIN' ON,
AND I GET THE MASA,
TASTE A LITTLE BIT OF THAT CORN.
DIG IT.
THE SPICES ARE PERFECT.
HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEET TO IT.
TURKEY WITH WORKS,
BRISKET AND BEANS.
BEST CHILI I'VE EVER HAD
IN MY LIFE.
THERE'S A LOT OF CHILI
IN THERE.
WHO HAD THE CHILI VERDE?
I DID, GOOD HOME FOOD,
EXCELLENT.
WE LIKE THIS PLACE A LOT.
I DON'T GO ANY PLACE ELSE.
MY FAVORITE.
IS THIS WHAT YOU WANTED IT
TO BE?
EXACTLY.
SO YOUR DREAM
HAS BEEN FULFILLED?
YES.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
I GOT LIKE 20 PIZZAS TO MAKE.
(Guy)
WE'RE HEADIN' TO ARIZONA...
RIGHT UP THERE
WITH MY GRANDMOTHER'S COOKING.
(Guy)
WHERE THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
FAMILY RECIPES LIKE CLOCKWORK.
I'M HERE IN GLENDALE, ARIZONA,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF PHOENIX
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT'S GOT
A GREAT TRIPLE D HISTORY.
NOW THE GRANDFATHER
USED TO OWN
THE BENDIX DINER,
A REAL LEGEND IN NEW JERSEY.
THE DAD'S A GRADUATE
OF CULINARY SCHOOL,
AND THE SON'S BEEN MAKIN' PIZZA
SINCE HE WAS 13 YEARS OLD.
NOW THE SON AND DAD
HAVE PAIRED UP TOGETHER
HERE AT THIS BRICK OVEN
PIZZA JOINT
AND NAMED IT
AFTER THEIR FAMILY, LA PIAZZA.
TWO PESTOS TO GO.
WHAT DO I LOOK LIKE,
A CATERER?
MAKE THAT COFFEE TO GO,
WILL YOU?
(Guy)
YEP, IT'S A WELL OILED
FATHER AND SON MACHINE.
BAKIN' A CAKE OVER HERE
OR WHAT?
(Guy)
RUN BY DENNIS PIAZZA
AND HIS SON JUSTIN,
A COUPLE OF JERSEY GUYS...
WHAT A WAY TO EAT!
(Guy)
WHO BROUGHT THEIR HOME COOKIN'
TRADITIONS WITH THEM
WHEN THEIR FAMILY
MOVED TO ARIZONA.
THEN THEY OPENED THIS JOINT.
LIFE'S TOO SHORT
TO EAT BAD FOOD.
WE USE FRESH MOZZARELLA,
WE MAKE OUR OWN DOUGH,
WE MAKE OUR OWN SAUCES.
IT'S JUST AWESOME.
HANDMADE.
REALLY GOOD FRESH TOPPINGS.
ENJOY.
(Guy)
ON ALL KINDS OF PIES.
MARGHERITA PIZZA,
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
THEIR WHITE PIZZAS
ARE PHENOMENAL.
(Guy)
AND THIS ONE'S
JUST BEEN INVENTED.
MEDITERRANEAN PIZZA.
(Guy)
WITH PESTO ALFREDO SAUCE,
MOZZARELLA,
AND SUN DRIED TOMATOES.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
THE MEDITERRANEAN.
LET'S DO IT.
WHEAT FLOUR FROM ITALY,
THAT'S WHAT THE KEY
TO OUR RECIPE IS.
SO I TURN THE MIXER ON,
PUT IN LUKEWARM WATER.
ACTIVATE THE YEAST,
LET IT SIT FOR A SECOND.
SUGAR, SALT...
LET THAT MIX EVENLY
THROUGH THERE.
THEN I POUR THE YEAST IN,
NOW THE WATER.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
AND THEN LET IT MIX USUALLY
ABOUT 10 TO 15 MINUTES.
I LEAVE IT IN A BIG BALL
ON THE TABLE,
THROW A PLASTIC BAG ON IT,
LET IT SIT,
LET IT SWEAT A LITTLE BIT.
SO NOW WE'RE READY
TO UNVEIL THE MASTERPIECE
AND START TRIMMIN' IT DOWN?
TWELVE OUNCES,
USUALLY GET IT ON PRETTY CLOSE.
ELEVEN AND A HALF,
LET ME GET A SHOT AT THIS.
BEAT ME AT MY OWN PLACE,
IT'S NOT COOL.
AH-HA!
YOU'RE ON THE MONEY TODAY.
OKAY, SO THEN YOU'RE GONNA
ROLL BACK IN.
I ROLL IT IN.
MAKE A NICE CLEAN BALL.
A LITTLE OIL
IN THE BOTTOM OF THE PAN.
PUT IT DOWN,
TURN IT THE OTHER WAY.
MAKE SURE BOTH SIDES
GET A LITTLE OIL ON IT.
FLOUR IT UP, STRETCH IT OUT,
AND THEN JUST GIVE IT
A LITTLE TWIRL.
THERE YOU GO, NICE AND SOFT,
NICE AND THIN.
FRESH MOZZARELLA GOES ON FIRST.
IT'S GOT HOMEMADE PESTO
ALFREDO SAUCE.
WE'LL PUT THE PESTO IN THERE
AND WHIP THAT UP.
THAT'S THE SAUCE
THAT GOES ON THE PIZZA.
I WILL ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SHREDDED MOZZARELLA.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
ON THIS ONE,
OREGANO, IN THE OVEN.
WATCH IT, MAKE SURE
THIS COOKS REAL GOOD HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
JUST GONNA TAKE IT OUT HERE,
SUN DRIED TOMATOES GO ON,
JUST GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
MORE...
CHEESE BOILING ON TOP
OF THE PIZZA SKIN.
FRESH FETA
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT, REALLY GOOD,
LOOK HOW THIN THAT IS.
THAT'S AMAZING.
I LIKE PIZZA CRUST
THAT HAS SOME BITE TO IT.
IF YOU GOTTA CHEW,
YOU GOTTA ENJOY IT.
THAT'S SOME REALLY
FLAVORFUL PESTO TOO.
I CAN DO AN ITSY-BITSY SPIDER
WITH THE MOZZARELLA CHEESE.
SO SIMPLE BUT WHEN
YOU USED GREAT INGREDIENTS,
SO GOOD.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL,
I WON'T EAT PIZZA ANYWHERE ELSE.
YOU CAN TELL
THAT IT'S FRESH MADE
AND THAT HE PUTS A LOT
OF HEART AND SOUL INTO IT.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S AN ART, FROM THE DOUGH
TO THE SAUCE TO THE CHEESE
AND HOW YOU PUT IT TOGETHER.
HE'S ONE OF THE BEST
YOU'VE SEEN?
HE'S THE BEST I KNOW OF.
CAN I SAVE THAT?
BECAUSE I DON'T THINK
I'LL EVER HEAR THAT EVER AGAIN.
(Guy)
BUT HEY, HE HAS BEEN DOING IT
SINCE HE WAS A KID.
ANOTHER ONE COMING IN.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY OTHER
PIZZA PLACE.
THIS RECIPE'S BEEN PASSED DOWN,
THIS ISN'T YOUR
AVERAGE PIZZA SAUCE.
(Guy)
AND THESE AREN'T
YOUR AVERAGE PIES.
FROM THE PORTOBELLO
TO A BLUE CHEESE CHEESE STEAK.
CRAZY GOOD.
(Guy)
AND THIS HEAVY HITTER.
ITALIAN STALLION.
(Guy)
FOUR KINDS OF MEAT
ON TOP OF...
FRESH MOZZARELLA SAUCE,
DRIZZLE IT ON.
BIG DELI-STYLE PEPPERONIS HERE.
THAT'S A LOT OF PEPPERONI.
SOPPRESSATA, WHICH IS
IMPORTED SALAMI.
DOES THAT DOOR STAY LOCKED
RIGHT OVER THERE
THE WHOLE TIME?
LOOK AT THIS GUY,
HE'S SABOTAGING MY PIES HERE.
NOW WE GOT PARMA PROSCIUTTO,
ALMOST GIVES IT
LIKE A BACON-TYPE EFFECT
WHEN IT COMES OUT OF THE OVEN.
ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
(Guy)
THE MEATS OUTWEIGH EVERYTHING
ELSE, INCLUDING THE DOUGH.
YEP, A LITTLE OREGANO ON TOP,
A LITTLE EXTRA VIRGIN
OLIVE OIL.
THAT'LL GIVE IT THE LITTLE KISS,
SEPARATE IT.
NOW HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
AT 800 DEGREES?
FOUR MINUTES.
YOU CAN JUST SEE EVERYTHING
STARTIN' TO CURL UP ON TOP
IN THERE.
COUPLE QUARTER TURNS
AND IT'S DONE.
THERE WE GO, CUT IT UP.
NEED A FORK OR MAYBE A BACKHOE.
IT'S GREAT, THERE IS
SO MUCH MEAT ON IT,
HOW DO PEOPLE EAT IT?
JUST LIKE YOU'RE DOIN'.
IT'S SO THIN
AND SO CRUNCHY,
AND I REALLY DO... I MEAN,
I LOVE FRESH MOZZARELLA.
VERY DELICIOUS PIE,
YOU CAN TASTE THE PEPPERONI,
SEPARATE FROM THE SAUSAGE,
FROM THE PROSCIUTTO.
IT'S JUST GOOD,
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU'S GOOD,
PLUS IT'S HOME.
(Guy)
IT'S JUST LIKE IT WAS
IN DENNIS' HOUSE
WHEN HE WAS A KID.
MUSSELS IN MARINARA.
FABULOUS.
(Guy)
LINGUINI WITH CLAM SAUCE.
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
(Guy)
AND SOMETHING CALLED
SPAGHETTI PIE WHEN WE COME BACK.
IT'S A LUNCH PORTION.
A LUNCH PORTION.
NOW WE'RE ROLLIN'.
(Guy)
AT LA PIAZZA
IN GLENDALE, ARIZONA...
I GOT LIKE 20 PIZZAS TO MAKE.
(Guy)
JUSTIN PIAZZA IS CRANKING
OUT THE PIES.
EVERYBODY EATIN' OUT THERE?
(Guy)
AND HIS DAD DENNIS IS DOING
THE REST OF THE FAMILY COOKBOOK.
CHICKEN PESTO LASAGNA.
THE MUSSELS, JUST FABULOUS.
(Guy)
AND THIS FAMILY FAVORITE...
BAKED SPAGHETTI PIE.
(Guy)
THAT DENNIS PICKED UP
FROM HIS GRANDMOTHER.
BAKED SPAGHETTI PIE.
SIMILAR TO LASAGNA,
BUT MADE WITH SPAGHETTI.
SO WHAT ARE WE ON NOW?
HOMEMADE MARINARA SAUCE,
FRESH PARSLEY
AND SOME FRESH BASIL,
AND A LITTLE
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
I JUST FINE CHOP THAT
WITH SOME FRESH GARLIC.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
EXTRA VIRGIN ON THAT
AND JUST A QUICK...
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT THE
FRESH HERBS IN THE HEAT
RIGHT NOW.
CELERY, CARROT, ONION,
JUST A QUICK CHOP.
THIS IS YOUR MAGICAL
BASKET HERE.
GARLIC, SOME ITALIAN SEASONING,
SOME BAY LEAF, SALT...
GROUND ANISE SEED, BASIL,
GRANULATED ONION, BLACK PEPPER.
NOW I TAKE EXTRA VIRGIN,
GOOD RED WINE.
I LET THIS SWEAT
FOR ABOUT FOUR OR FIVE MINUTES
AND ADD MY TOMATOES.
SLOW AND LOW
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
AND A LITTLE SPAGHETTI.
DUMP THOSE IN FOR ME,
AND I'LL GET THAT GOING,
A LITTLE SPAGHETTI THERE.
DENNIS IS ALREADY WORKIN'
AND I'M ALREADY WORKIN'.
PUT YOUR RICOTTA IN.
THE RICOTTA, THIS IS
THE MARINARA THAT WE MADE.
CREAM.
TWO CUPS.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT
STIRRING THE PASTA?
MY ARM'S GETTIN' TIRED,
BUT I THINK I CAN MAKE IT HERE.
I MEAN, LET ME KNOW IF THIS
IS GETTIN' TOO MUCH FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
REGGIANO, ASIAGO.
PECORINO ROMANO.
SHEEP'S MILK?
YOU GOT IT.
NICE AND SHARP,
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
JUST GIVE IT
A NICE LITTLE STIR THERE.
SO IT'S GOT KIND OF
A ROSY COLOR TO IT.
GOTTA WORK FOR IT ALL.
HEY!
SO YOU'RE GONNA GO
DRAIN THE PASTA.
AND COME RIGHT BACK.
ALL RIGHT, HAVE A NICE TIME,
I'LL BE RIGHT HERE.
BACK ALREADY, WHENEVER YOUR
MIXTURE'S READY, GO AHEAD...
ALL RIGHT, MIXTURE GOES DOWN.
COUPLE OF LADLES OF MARINARA,
FRESH MOZZARELLA.
I COOKED THE PASTA AL DENTE,
BECAUSE WHEN I GO ON THE
OTHER ONE,
I DON'T WANT IT TO BECOME MUSH.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT!
THE SHOW'S CALLED
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
I TRAVEL AROUND THE COUNTRY,
AND I WATCH OTHER PEOPLE
COOK IN THEIR RESTAURANT.
RIGHT, WELL,
I LIKE HOW YOU COOK.
I CAN GIVE YOU A JOB HERE
ANY TIME.
NOW A LITTLE BIT OF REGGIANO,
A LITTLE PLASTIC.
THAT KEEPS IN THE MOISTURE.
HERE'S A LITTLE ALUMINUM
FOR YOU.
KEEPS THE PLASTIC FROM
MELTING OFF.
RIGHT INTO THE OVEN,
350 FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
THERE YOU GO,
THAT'S THE FINISHED PRODUCT.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY! TAKE
THIS,
A NICE PIECE LIKE THAT.
PUT A NICE LADLE OF SAUCE HERE,
SOME FRESH MOZZARELLA,
AND I'M GONNA GO RIGHT INTO
THE WOOD-FIRED OVEN WITH THIS.
GOOD TO GO, A LITTLE SAUCE,
A LITTLE PARSLEY ON TOP.
A LITTLE PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO,
AND THERE'S YOUR BIG
SPAGHETTI PIE LUNCH.
WHEW, LOOK AT THAT!
MMM, GREAT TEXTURE,
THE FRESH MOZZARELLA ON TOP,
THE HANDMADE SAUCE,
DELICIOUS, NICE JOB, MAN.
JUST PLAIN GOOD.
YOU CAN TELL IT'S FRESH MADE,
OH, I LOVE THIS PLACE.
LITTLE FETA CHEESE, PLEASE.
IT'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH MY GRANDMOTHER'S COOKING.
YOU HAVE ENOUGH FOOD?
WHATEVER THE PEOPLE WANT HERE,
THAT'S WHAT WE MAKE.
I DON'T GO TO WORK,
I COME HERE AND I MAKE PIZZAS.
JUST LISTEN, I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON.
I HAD FUN, IT'S REALLY
BEEN NICE, REALLY NICE.
CONGRATULATIONS, BROTHER,
AWESOME JOINT!
SO THAT'S ALL FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE'RE HEADED
FOR SOME MORE GREAT JOINTS.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
I DON'T WANT A LITTLE
TWO-SECOND DANCE.
HIT IT!
HEY!
GET OUTTA HERE, GET,
GET OUTTA HERE!