HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
HEADING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
MACARONI AND CHEESE.
DEFINITELY THE REAL THING.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
FOOD THE WAY
MY MOTHER MAKES IT.
HOME-STYLE
IN TACOMA WASHINGTON...
OH, I'M GONNA GET
SOME BISCUITS GOIN'.
SOUTHERN CLASSICS...
GRITS.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
JUST LIKE DOWN-HOME.
FROM A TRUE
SOUTHERN COOK.
IT'S REAL FOOD.
MMM. OH...
(mumbles)
THAT'S IT, HUH?
IN ARIZONA...
SHRIMP RAVIOLI.
ITALIAN FAVORITES.
PENNE BOLOGNESE.
AUTHENTIC ITALIAN.
PARMIGIANA.
THIS DUDE BROUGHT BACK...
(speaking indistinctly)
AFTER LIVING IN TUSCANY.
THE FOOD THING THERE
IS... PASSION.
IT'S EVERYBODY'S
EVERYTHING.
THAT'S WHA-WHA-WHA!
AND THE ADOBE DINER
IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO.
87.
DOING COMFORT FOOD...
MEATLOAF IS THE BEST.
SOUTHWESTERN STYLE.
GREEN CHILE
IS WHAT MAKES THAT.
YOU CAN'T COME TO NEW MEXICO
AND NOT EAT OUR GREEN CHILI.
RIGHT. YOU HAVE
A PROBLEM IF YOU DO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
♪♪
SO TRIPLE "D" HERE
IN TACOMA, WASHINGTON.
NOW LET'S SEE--WE'VE HAD PIZZA
IN KNOXVILLE, TENNESSEE.
WE'VE HAD CHINESE FOOD
IN PHOENIX, ARIZONA.
SO IT'S ONLY FITTING THAT
WHEN WE COME TO THE NORTHWEST,
WE WOULD HAVE, UH--
YEAH, SOUTHERN FOOD.
GOTTA CHECK OUT
SOUTHERN KITCHEN.
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS,
LET'S GET Y'ALL SET UP
WITH SOME OF THIS HERE.
JUST GOOD
SOUTHERN COOKIN'.
COLLARD GREENS.
MESS OF GREENS.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES--
I JUST LOVE THEM.
OH, I'M GONNA GET
SOME BISCUITS GOIN'.
IT REMINDS ME OF MY MOTHER'S
AND GRANDMOTHER'S COOKIN'.
I LOVE WHAT THIS RESTAURANT
IS SAYING--
IT MAKES PEOPLE GO BACK
TO THEIR ROOTS.
WINGS OUT.
LIKE GLORIA MARTIN DID
14 YEARS AGO
WHEN SHE BOUGHT THIS JOINT...
CHICKEN GOIN'.
AND STARTED COOKIN'
LIKE HER DAD.
HE WAS A SOUTHERN COOK.
HE WAS A MILITARY COOK, SO HE
TAUGHT ME A LOT ABOUT COOKING.
EVERYTHING'S REALLY FRESH
EVERY TIME I COME HERE.
IT'S REAL FOOD.
GRITS, HASH BROWNS,
HOME FRIES.
MAC AND CHEESE
AND FRIED CHICKEN.
I'M FROM THE SOUTH.
SO IT'S LIKE SOUTHERN
FRIED CHICKEN. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
NUMBER ONE SPECIALTY
HERE IS WHAT?
FRIED CHICKEN.
I BEEN WANTIN' THIS
FOR THE LAST WEEK.
WHAT MAKES GREAT FRIED CHICKEN,
IN YOUR OPINION?
BASICALLY, I THINK
IT'S SLOW-COOKING IT.
INSTEAD OF 350,
WE DO 325.
IT IS GOOD.
WELL, I'M DONE
WITH THE QUESTIONS.
NOW I'M READY
FOR THE TUTELAGE.
WELL, WE START
WITH AN EGG WASH.
THIS IS BASICALLY COLOR,
YOU KNOW, A LITTLE TEXTURE.
JUST THE YOLKS?
YES. THE WHITES MAKE THE CRUST
TOO CRISPY AND HARD.
SO WE JUST DO THE YOLKS.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME WATER
TO THE EGG YOLKS AND MAKE
A NICE LITTLE BATH WITH IT.
I THINK EGG YOLK'S
A PRETTY COLOR.
YEAH, BUT YOU DON'T EVER
HEAR ANYTHING CALLED, LIKE--
"HEY, THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
CAR THERE. WHAT COLOR IS THAT?"
EGG YOLK.
"THAT'S EGG YOLK."
THAT'S A GREAT LOOKIN'
EGG YOLK JACKET YOU HAVE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD FLOUR.
REGULAR ALL-PURPOSE?
THAT'S ALL IT IS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
OUR OWN SEASONING SALT.
WHEN YOU GO INTO A PLACE,
AND THEY'RE MAKING
THEIR OWN SEASONING SALT,
YOU'RE--
YOU'RE KIND OF MAKING
YOUR DISTINCT FLAVOR.
IT'S FUN.
A LITTLE GARLIC?
GARLIC POWDER, YOU GOT IT.
BLACK PEPPER.
WE'LL JUST GIVE IT
A NICE MIX HERE.
WE'RE READY
FOR THE CHICKEN.
GETTIN' WET.
MM-HMM, AND THEN
WE COME THIS WAY.
SO YOU GO WASH, FLOUR,
WASH, FLOUR?
WASH, FLOUR. MM-HMM.
IS THAT TYPICAL?
YES. I LIKE
DOING THIS PART--
PATTIN' IT AND MAKIN' SURE
THAT IT'S OKAY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T GET
THIS KIND OF ATTENTION
AT A DAY SPA. I MEAN...
OH, COME ON.
JUST SHAKE IT OFF,
'CAUSE IN THE FRYER,
ALL THIS FLOUR GETS IN THERE
AND IT BURNS THE FLOUR UP.
YEAH, YOU GOTTA DO
A LITTLE SHAKE.
NOW DO YOU PUT 'EM IN
AT DIFFERENT TIMES
AND PULL 'EM OUT
AT DIFFERENT TIMES?
YEAH, BREAST, THIGH,
LEG AND WING--
THE THIGH AND THE BREAST
TAKE SO LONG TO COOK.
MMM.
THE WING AND THE LEG
WILL COME OUT FIRST.
OKAY, WE'LL LET IT WORK.
20 MINUTES?
AND YOU CAN ALWAYS TELL
WHEN THE CHICKEN'S DONE--
WHEN IT FEELS LIGHT.
I THINK THEY'RE DONE.
YOU GONNA GIVE ME THE--
I'LL GIVE YOU
A TRIAL PIECE.
THE PICK-IT-UP TEST.
CAN I FEEL?
YEAH, YOU BET.
OH!
FEELS LIGHTER?
20 MORE SECONDS.
THERE WE GO.
GOOD CRUST ON IT.
MM-HMM.
MMM. GOOD.
THANK YOU.
NOT TOO SALTY
AND NOT OVERPOWERING.
I'M THE GUY THAT'S ALWAYS
PUTTING SOME KIND OF SAUCE
ON IT, LIKE SOME
HOT VINEGAR.
OH, THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN'
ABOUT RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT, YEAH.
YOU MAKE THE SAUCE?
MM-HMM.
DISTILLED WHITE VINEGAR,
SUGAR, PEPPER--
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
OH...
(mumbles)
IT'S HOT!
WHAT?
IT'S CRISPY, TENDER, MOIST--
DEFINITELY THE REAL THING.
ARE YOU GONNA
EAT ALL THAT,
OR YOU WANT ME TO HELP
YOU WITH THOSE WINGS?
I GOT IT.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD,
JUST LIKE DOWN-HOME.
WE GOT SOME SWEET TEA.
STRAWBERRY LEMONADE'S GOOD.
YUMMY.
GREEN TOMATOES, PLEASE!
YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE SOMEWHERE IN THE SOUTH.
SOUTHERN FOOD IS ACTUALLY
AMERICA'S ORIGINAL CUISINE.
I'M FROM GEORGIA.
I WANTED A LITTLE BIT OF HOME
TODAY, AND I GOT THAT.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
FROM THE CHICKEN
TO THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
AND BATTERED CATFISH.
I'M REALLY ENJOYING IT.
SERVED UP
WITH ALL THE SOUTHERN SIDES.
I NEED A BAG OF OKRA, PLEASE.
OKAY, HERE COMES THE YAMS.
THE HUSH PUPPIES.
THEY ARE EXCELLENT.
LOOK AT ALL
THE JALAPEñO IN THAT.
MMM.
GRITS AND FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
I LIKE THE BATTER.
THAT'S THE WHOLE TRICK--IF YOU
HAVE A GOOD BATTER OR NOT.
LOOK AT THAT. UH-HUH.
GREAT TEXTURE
ON THE OUTSIDE.
THE RIGHT SIDE--
THAT'S THE KEY.
A LITTLE BIT OF SOURNESS
OF THE TOMATO BEING GREEN.
YEAH.
NOT OVER SEASONED
NOT TOO SALTY.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'VE NEVER HAD
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES,
SO I GUESS I'M KIND OF
GREEN ON FRIED GREEN TOMATOES,
BUT I JUST LOVE THEM.
I HAVEN'T LIVED
IN THE SOUTH.
I JUST AM A PERSON WHO LOVES
PHENOMENAL FOOD, AND I CAME HERE
TODAY 'CAUSE I REALLY WANTED
CORN BREAD STUFFING.
WHAT'S SO GOOD ABOUT IT?
JUST THE FACT THAT
IT'S MADE WITH CORN BREAD.
WE MAKE THE CORN BREAD
SPECIFICALLY JUST FOR
THE DRESSING?
YES.
AND HOW DO WE GET STARTED?
OH, I KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
SO YOU SAVE
ALL THE BACON FAT?
YES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
USE THAT?
YES, TO SAUTé.
GONNA BE A GOOD DAY
WHEN YOU WORK UP A SWEAT
DIGGING OUT
YOUR BACON FAT.
GONNA PUT
SOME ONIONS IN HERE.
NOW SOME CELERY.
UH-HUH.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA
SWEAT THIS DOWN.
IT'S GONNA GO DOWN UNTIL
THE ONIONS ARE CLEAR.
AND THEN WE'LL INCORPORATE
WITH THE OTHER INGREDIENTS.
CORRECT.
CRUMBLE SOME CORN BREAD.
YEAH.
VERY DENSE CORN BREAD.
IT IS DENSE.
NOW WHAT GOES IN?
CHICKEN STOCK.
YOU MAKE IT YOURSELF?
OH, YEAH, MM-HMM.
I LIKE THAT.
AND SOME BUTTER.
PUT SOME THYME IN THERE.
FRESH THYME?
OH, YEAH.
ROSEMARY AND SAVORY.
SOME SAVORY?
YES.
I DON'T SEE SAVORY
GET COOKED WITH A LOT.
MM-HMM.
AND SOME SAGE.
GOTTA HAVE SAGE
IN STUFFING.
I KNOW.
AND SOME MILK.
AND THEN OUR ONION,
CELERY AND BACON FAT.
BACON FAT'S THE KICKER.
MMM.
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA STIR IT.
STIR IT ALL UP, AND HOW LONG
DOES IT GO IN THE OVEN?
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
30 MINUTES.
DRESSING READY?
YES, IT IS.
OKAY. LOOK AT THAT.
WHOA.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE
BIT OF OUR GRAVY ON IT.
DO YOU MAKE YOUR GRAVY?
WE DO MAKE IT.
WHOA.
THERE WE GO. TRY THAT.
MMM. IT'S GREAT.
SO YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEETNESS
FROM THE CORN BREAD ITSELF.
THEN YOU GET THE SAVORY PIECE--
THE ONIONS AND THE CELERY--
THAT COMES THROUGH...
MM-HMM.
BUT THE REAL KEY IS THE TEXTURE
OF THE CORN BREAD.
YEAH. YOU SHOULD JUST CALL
YOURSELF "THE STUFFING HOUSE."
OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
MMM.
IT'S REALLY MOIST,
AND I LOVE THE GRAVY.
CORN BREAD DRESSING
PICK UP, PLEASE!
WHEN YOU COME IN AND YOU CAN
SMELL ALL THE SEASONINGS,
AND YOU CAN GET
THE VIBE OF IT.
IT ACTUALLY TASTES
LIKE SOMEONE PUT
THEIR HEART AND SOUL
INTO THE FOOD.
THE OWNER MISS GLORIA
IS SO FRIENDLY.
(Gloria) I JUST WANT THEM
TO HAVE THE EXPERIENCE
OF KNOWING THAT THEIR FOOD
WAS MADE WITH CARE AND LOVE.
REALLY, YOU KNOW?
AND IT'S--IT'S WHOLE FOOD.
ARE THOSE TWO OF THE COOKS
BACK THERE--CARE AND LOVE?
YES--NO!
CUT IT--NO, NO, NO, NO.
UP NEXT...
ABSOLUTELY SPECTACULAR.
WE'RE HEADING TO PHOENIX...
IT'S DIVINE.
FOR A TASTE OF FLORENCE.
BOY, YOU SURE BROUGHT
SOME GEMS BACK FROM ITALY.
YEAH.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
CRAZY GOOD.
MY GREAT GRANDFATHER'S NAME
WAS GIUSEPPE FIERI,
AND OF COURSE
I LOVE ITALIAN FOOD.
NOW I'M DOWN HERE
IN PHOENIX, ARIZONA,
WHERE MOST PEOPLE
WOULD EXPECT,
WELL, SOUTHWESTERN
OR MEXICAN FOOD.
SO YOU KNOW I GOTTA
JUMP AT THE SHOT
TO TRY SOME OLD-SCHOOL
ITALIAN COOKING,
HERE AT GIUSEPPE'S ON 28th.
HEY, CINDY, I GOT YOU
A BOLOGNESE. HERE IT IS.
AUTHENTIC ITALIAN.
HE'S GOT THE FRESH PASTA.
IT'S DIVINE.
I LOVE MY OSSO BUCO.
ABSOLUTELY SPECTACULAR.
THAT'S WHA-WHA-WHA!
HERE YOU GO, DARLIN'.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT
THIS PLACE?
NUMBER ONE--THE FOOD,
AND NUMBER TWO--
THE WAIT STAFF AND RICH.
WHAT'S THE MATTER, YOU?
HE'S A KICK.
HE IS OWNER RICH BOCK...
CHEERS, GUYS.
AN ITALIAN FOOD FANATIC...
SHRIMP RAVIOLI.
AND A WORLD-CLASS MUSICIAN...
(Rich) I ENDED UP PLAYING
PROFESSIONALLY IN NEW YORK,
GOT A CHANCE
TO GO TO ITALY.
AND LANDED A GIG
IN FLORENCE.
I WAS THERE
NINE YEARS AND CHANGE.
THE FOOD THING THERE IS--
YOU KNOW, IT'S EVERYBODY'S HOBBY
AND PASSION.
EVERYBODY'S EVERYTHING.
EVERYTHING.
BEAUTIFUL.
(speaking indistinctly)
SO WHEN HE CAME
BACK TO THE STATES,
HE BROUGHT
THE RECIPES WITH HIM,
AND SEVEN YEARS AGO,
GOT THIS PLACE ROLLING.
NUMBER ONE ITEM
ON THE MENU EVERYBODY LOVES?
THE BOLOGNESE RAGU.
IT'S NOT LIKE THE MEAT SAUCE
I MAKE AT HOME, THAT'S FOR SURE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
VERY MEATY.
I HAVE TO TALK
SOME PEOPLE INTO IT,
BUT ONCE
THEY GIVE IT A GO...
YOU OWN 'EM.
I GOT 'EM.
SO IT'S BOLOGNESE TIME.
RAGU TIME.
GET IT ON.
HOT POT,
WE THROW IN THE BEEF.
HERE'S 5 POUNDS OF SAUSAGE
AND GROUND TURKEY.
WHO DID THE RECIPE
COME FROM?
THE WIFE OF ONE OF MY GREAT
TENNIS PALS BACK IN FLORENCE.
SHE WAS BIG ON MIXING
POULTRY AND MEATS.
FANTASTIC.
SO NOW WE JUST BREAK THIS UP,
LET IT BROWN A LITTLE BIT.
SWEAT OUT SOME BACON.
RENDER OUT THE FAT.
YEP, AND THEN I TAKE THE BACON
OUT, I PUT THE BACON IN HERE.
AND THEN USE THIS
TO SWEAT THOSE VEGGIES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ADD A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
TO THE BACON FAT.
RED ONIONS, CELERY...
THIS IS RIGHT UP THE LINES
OF MY BOLOGNESE.
CARROTS, WHEN THE VEGETABLES
HAVE SOFTENED A LITTLE BIT,
PUT IN SOME
CHOPPED GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT, A LITTLE PEPPER.
THE REAL DEAL.
SO THIS IS A LITTLE WINE I MAKE
WITH A GOOD PAL OF MINE.
REALLY?
YEAH, RUBY CABERNET.
WE MAKE IT EVERY YEAR.
NOTHIN' I DON'T LIKE MORE
THAN A LITTLE WINE
IN SOME GROUND-UP MEAT.
OH, THAT SMELLS GREAT.
NOW I'M GONNA PUT
SOME TOMATO PASTE IN.
GOTTA COOK THAT DOWN.
SOME "TI-MO"--THYME
AND ROSEMARY COMBINATION.
AND THAT WAS FRESH THAT
YOU GROUND UP YOURSELF.
FRESH, YES.
YOU CAN TELL BECAUSE
OF HOW DARK IT IS.
LET THAT DO ITS THING
FOR FIVE, TEN MINUTES.
THEN I'M GONNA PUT ALL
THE TOMATO PASTE MIXTURE
IN WITH THE MEAT.
I THROW IN SOME WATER.
NO MORE TOMATO SAUCE?
NO MORE TOMATO.
SERIOUSLY?
YEP.
MINE WAS
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
THIS IS MEAT TIMES TEN.
RAW CHICKEN LEGS.
LOOKS LIKE
VOODOO BOLOGNESE.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA STICK
SOME CHICKEN LEGS IN THERE?
AFTER TWO HOURS, I TAKE 'EM OUT,
I TAKE THE MEAT OFF,
CHOP IT UP, THROW THE MEAT
BACK IN, AND THAT'S IT.
SO NOW I PUT
THE CHICKEN LIVERS IN.
OH, THOSE LOOK
SO GOOD RAW.
THIS WOULD GO
FOR ANOTHER HOUR NOW.
AND IT'S HEADIN'
FOR SOME HOMEMADE PASTA.
WE MAKE THESE TAGLIATELLE
JUST ON THE WEEKEND.
PEOPLE ARE HERE AT 5:00
FOR FRESH PASTA,
AND WHEN IT'S OVER, IT'S OVER.
PUT IT ON OUR NEW-AGE RACK.
THIS IS INSTEAD OF THE BACK
OF YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S CHAIR.
NOW WE CUT THESE UP,
AND WE'RE ROCKIN'.
THAT'S SOME NICE
FRESH-MADE PASTA.
SALTED WATER.
I'M BARELY ABLE TO TALK
RIGHT NOW 'CAUSE OF THE DROOL.
SO THAT'S HOT AND READY TO GO.
LOOK AT HOW THAT BROKE DOWN.
IN?
YES, IN WE GO.
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
OH, OH! SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
IN A LITTLE ITALIAN JOINT
IN A STRIP MALL?
YOU BET, YOU BET.
A LITTLE PARSLEY.
OKAY, WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
SIGNORE, FORCHETTA.
YES, I WILL NOT
FOR-GET-A YOU, EITHER.
YES.
LOOK AT THIS.
HOLD ME.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
ISN'T THAT GREAT?
MMM.
GOD, MINE SUCKS
COMPARED TO THIS.
THAT WAS SWEET.
NO, SERIOUSLY.
MMM, THE MEAT--
IT'S SO NICE AND TENDER,
AND THE PASTA
JUST IS THE PERFECT--
WOW, THAT'S GOOD. YOU'VE GOTTA
COME TRY THIS. CRAZY GOOD.
IT'S PERFECT.
WONDERFUL COMBINATION OF MEATS.
THAT'S ABOUT AS OLD SCHOOL
AS YOU GET.
OLD SCHOOL.
HE KNOWS HOW TO MAKE FOOD
THE WAY MY MOTHER MAKES IT.
LET'S PUT SOME PASTA
IN THERE.
YOU JUST WOULDN'T
EXPECT SOMETHING
THIS GOOD, THIS AUTHENTIC
IN A STRIP MALL.
THE SHRIMP RAVIOLI.
IN A LITTLE JOINT
WITH ONLY 12 TABLES.
WE GOT ABOUT
1,000 SQUARE FEET,
AND ABOUT 600 OF IT
IS PROBABLY THE KITCHEN.
I WAS GONNA SAY--60/40.
IT'S QUAINT, IT'S FUN.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
FROM CLASSICS LIKE SPAGHETTI
CARBONARA WITH PANCETTA...
MMM.
TO CALAMARI BRAISED
IN WHITE WINE AND RED SAUCE.
ALL THIS FOOD
I LEARNED FROM FRIENDS
AND THE MOTHERS
OF FRIENDS.
WITH THE OCCASIONAL
RICH TWIST.
WHEN I HAVE THE TIME, I TRY
TO DO SOMETHING THAT I HAVEN'T
BEEN DOING--A DIFFERENT
DESSERT OR A DIFFERENT DISH.
LIKE OSSO BUCO
DONE THREE WAYS...
OSSO BUCO READY.
CLASSIC VEAL OR BEEF...
OSSA BUCO FOR YOU.
OR THE FAN FAVORITE HERE...
THESE ARE PORK SHANKS.
PORK SHANKS OUT OF IT.
I TRIED THE PORK,
AND PEOPLE ARE LOVING IT.
JUST A LITTLE SALT,
AND I'M GONNA ADD PEPPER.
WOW YOU'RE VERY GENTLE
WITH THE SEASONING ON THAT.
WELL, THERE'S A LOT
GOING ON HERE.
RIGHT, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
LIGHTLY FLOUR THESE.
JUST ON THE ENDS, HUH?
YEAH. HOT PAN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU PUT A LITTLE
SEAR ON THE TOP AND THE BOTTOM.
ABOUT THREE, FOUR
MINUTES ON A SIDE.
OKAY, THE LITTLE CRUST.
ALL RIGHT, I'M DOWN
WITH WHERE WE ARE.
PUT SOME MORE OIL IN THE PAN.
GONNA SAUTé MY VEGETABLES.
YEAH, I LOVE THE RED ONION.
DID YOU SEE THAT GETTING USED
PREDOMINANTLY IN ITALY?
IN FLORENCE WHERE I WAS--
ONLY RED ONION.
CARROTS, CELERY. LET THIS
SWEAT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
CELERY.
I HAD A LITTLE TOO MUCH
BOLOGNESE. SEE THE DROOPY EYES?
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
THROW IN SOME GARLIC,
MY FAVORITE--ROSEMARY
AND THYME--I JUST LOVE THAT.
I GIVE IT A STIR.
I'M JUST GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT DOWN ON THE BOTTOM.
NOW I'M JUST GONNA PUT
THE OSSO BUCO ON TOP.
I'M GONNA PUT THE REST
OF THE VEGETABLES IN,
JUST EVERYWHERE.
IT'S LIKE GARDEN MADNESS.
IT IS.
A LITTLE TOMATO SAUCE?
A LITTLE TOMATO SAUCE.
SO FAR, SO GREAT.
A LITTLE WINE.
OH. 375 DEGREES
FOR HOW LONG?
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
I CAN'T WAIT.
NUGGETS OF HAPPINESS.
I CAN JUST TOUCH IT
AND JUST SEE IT'S FALLING--
PAN'S HOT.
CAME OUT OF THE OVEN.
OH.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PASTA THAT COMPLEMENTS THIS?
YES.
A LITTLE OIL, A LITTLE LEMON,
A LITTLE PARSLEY.
WE PUT THE PASTA IN,
GIVE THIS A TOSS.
OH, THAT FRESH PASTA
JUST ROCKS.
LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL DRIPPINGS.
LOOK AT THE WAY IT JUST PULLS
RIGHT AWAY FROM THAT BONE.
ANYTIME YOU CAN COOK THE MEAT
NEXT TO THAT BIG OF A BONE,
THE FLAVOR'S GOTTA BE
JUST INTENSE.
YEAH.
MMM. WOW.
THAT'S SO SUPER FLAVOR.
OH, MAN.
I NEVER HAD IT
WITH PORK SHANKS BEFORE.
NO?
WOW, WHAT A TREAT, AND A LITTLE
BIT OF THE MIREPOIX--
THE CARROTS AND THE CELERY--
REALLY NICE. DELICIOUS.
BOY, YOU SURE BROUGHT
SOME GEMS BACK FROM ITALY.
YEAH.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
IT IS ALWAYS REALLY GOOD.
CINDY, TABLE FOUR.
ALWAYS JUST REALLY NICE
COMING BACK HERE.
WE KNOW WE'RE GONNA GET
A GOOD MEAL,
AND WE'RE GONNA
ENJOY OURSELVES.
(all) CHIN CHIN.
IT'S A TOTAL DREAM.
I LOVE THE CLIENTELE.
SO MUCH FUN
AND SATISFYING.
I THINK THAT'S
THE MUSICIAN IN YOU.
THIS TIME YOU'RE JUST
PLAYING YOUR MASTERPIECE
ON THE CANVAS
OF THE PLATE.
THANK YOU.
WOW.
I'M OUT ON THAT.
NEXT STOP...
DINER AND ADOBE.
YEAH.
SANTA FE.
THIS IS REALLY
HOMETOWN STUFF.
GREAT GREEN CHILE HERE.
WHERE DINER COOKIN'...
RIGHT AWAY.
MEANS CORNED BEEF HASH
WITH A SOUTHWESTERN KICK.
MMM.
AND OFF HE GOES
WITH THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
SO CHECK IT OUT--
BY NOW, WE'RE ALL PRETTY
FAMILIAR WITH DINERS, RIGHT?
COMFORT FOOD,
MADE BY GREAT PEOPLE,
FAMILY ENVIRONMENT,
ECLECTIC MENUS--
NOW IN JERSEY, IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE STAINLESS STEEL DINER,
BUT IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO--
WELL, WELCOME
TO THE ADOBE DINER.
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT ZIA.
IS THAT ENCHILADA COMING?
COMFORT FOOD,
SOUTHWESTERN STYLE.
GREEN CHILE CHEESE FRIES
AND RED CHILE CHEESE FRIES.
UH-HUH.
AVOCADO GAZPACHO.
FABULOUS.
SMOKED SALMON QUESADILLA.
LOVE IT, MAN.
JODI, YOU'RE UP!
AND ALL THE DINER CLASSICS.
TUNA MELT, MEATLOAF...
FISH-AND-CHIPS, KING.
DINER GONE WILD.
THANKS TO OWNER
BETH DRAISCOL...
TABLE 65.
WHO'S BEEN SERVING IT UP HER
WAY FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS...
VERY FRESH.
AND ALMOST TOTALLY
FROM SCRATCH,
LIKE ORGANIC
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK,
HOUSE-BRINED CORNED BEEF...
YOU HAD ME AT HELLO
ON THIS.
I KNOW.
SHE'S EVEN SMOKING
HER OWN SALMON...
I CAN SMELL
THE SMOKED SALMON FROM HERE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOR HER SIGNATURE
QUESADILLA.
SMOKED SALMON...
SO HOW ARE WE
GONNA DO THIS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A RUB
WITH EQUAL PARTS SALT,
PEPPER...
A LITTLE CAYENNE, SO YOU GET
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT THERE.
THAT'S MY
MEASURING TECHNIQUE--
SOME OF THIS,
SOME OF THAT, SOME OF THIS.
WE'VE GOT ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER.
MIX IT UP, AND IT GOES
RIGHT ONTO THE SALMON.
HITTING IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF LIME JUICE.
AND WE'RE NOT GONNA
GO TO A SMOKER.
WE'RE GONNA
SMOKE IT IN HERE?
WE JUST PUT A BUNCH
OF HICKORY CHIPS IN HERE,
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
STEAM PAN INSERT,
THE SALMON GOES
RIGHT IN THERE.
GET A NICE LITTLE
SEAL ON THERE
SO YOU LOCK
THAT SMOKE IN.
AND OVER HERE
IT GOES.
OKAY, 45 MINUTES...
YEP.
AND THEN
QUESA-DILL-IA TIME.
SO THE SALMON IS DONE.
GOOD LOOKIN'.
MMM, GREAT. SO HOW
DO WE MAKE ONE OF THESE?
WE USE FLOUR TORTILLAS
FOR THIS.
BUT A NICE, THICK
FLOUR TORTILLA.
AND THEN WE PUT
ASADERO CHEESE ON THIS.
WHAT--ASADERO?
ASADERO IS A MEXICAN
MELTING CHEESE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GOOD TEXTURE TO IT.
SOME CARAMELIZED SHALLOTS
AND OUR SMOKED SALMON.
(whistles)
GENEROUS PORTION.
AND NOW THIS IS GONNA
GO INTO THE PIZZA OVEN.
JUST ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
THREE MINUTES.
THERE'S OUR NICE
MELTED ASADERO CHEESE,
AND WE ARE GOING TO SLICE UP
SOME AVOCADO TO PUT ON THAT,
THERE WE GO, AND LET'S CUT
THAT BIG BOY UP.
THIS IS A SWEET
RED CHILE SAUCE WE MAKE.
(giggles)
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
THAT IS A BALANCE OF FLAVORS
THAT COMPLEMENT
EACH OTHER SO WELL.
YOU PUT SOME NICE HEAT
ON IT--MMM--
THEN YOU BRING THE SWEETNESS IN
FROM THE CARAMELIZED SHALLOTS.
MM-HMM.
THAT CHEESE HAS GOT
SOME NICE SALTINESS TO IT.
AND THE CREAMINESS
OF THE AVOCADO--
MMM, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU LIKE IT.
EVERY TIME I COME IN HERE,
I THINK,
I'M GONNA EAT SOMETHING ELSE,
AND I END UP EATING THE SALMON.
SAME THING AGAIN.
EVERY TIME.
WITH THAT SMOKED FLAVOR
OF THE SALMON
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT--LOVE IT, MAN.
JUST FRESH COOKED FOOD.
WE'VE GOT AN ASIAGO
WITH VINAIGRETTE.
WE BUY IT FROM THE FARMER'S
MARKET IN THE SUMMER.
WE BUY ALL OF OUR
BEEF FROM A RANCH
OUT IN EASTERN
NEW MEXICO.
ALL OF THE BEEF THAT
YOU'RE USING HERE IN ZIA
IS COMING FROM THIS RANCH?
THEY'RE ORGANIC,
THEY'RE GRASS-FED.
FOR THE BURGERS...
LOVE THEIR BURGERS.
THE MEATLOAF...
THE MEATLOAF IS THE BEST.
EVEN THE HOMEMADE
CORNED BEEF HASH.
ANY TIME SOMEONE
IS BRINING AND DOING
THEIR OWN CORNED BEEF
FROM THE BEGINNING...
YEP.
GIVE ME YOUR RUNDOWN HERE.
LOOKS LIKE SALT...
THERE'S OUR PAPRIKA,
ALLSPICE...
THYME.
BLACK PEPPER.
AND A LITTLE OF MY FAVORITE--
THE JUNIPER BERRIES.
AND LET'S NOT FORGET
THE BAY LEAVES.
I DIG IT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME SPICE RUB
DOWN, AND THEN OUR BRISKET.
THAT'S KIND OF THE FLAT
OF THE BRISKET.
WE GET MUCH BETTER
PENETRATION
IF YOU'RE NOT USING A BIG,
THICK PIECE OF MEAT.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
WRAP IT UP.
NOW YOU DO WANT
TO WEIGHT THIS DOWN.
PUT THE HEAVY TIN CANS
ON THERE, AND THEN--
IN THE WALK-IN IT GOES.
JUST LIKE THIS
INTO THE WALK-IN.
HOLDS IT BELOW 40 DEGREES
FOR 5 DAYS...
YEP.
WOW.
LOOK HOW MUCH
IT SHRINKS UP.
FIRST WE RINSE IT,
'CAUSE THERE'S AN AWFUL LOT
OF SALT ON THERE.
THEN IT GOES
INTO THE POT.
WE JUST PUT ENOUGH WATER
IN THERE TO COVER IT.
PUT IN SOME CARROTS,
SOME CELERY AND ONION.
SIMMER FOR THREE HOURS.
PULL IT OUT, LET IT COOL
AND THEN TEAR INTO IT.
WE CHOP IT.
OKAY, LIKE THIS?
1/2 INCH?
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WE PUT THE POTATOES
AND THE ONION IN FIRST.
OKAY.
THEN SOME BUTTER. WE LET
THAT COOK FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
AND THAT MEAT'S GOT
SOME SALT IN IT ALREADY...
YEAH.
SO I KIND OF
UNDER-SALT THIS.
SO WE'LL GO AHEAD AND PUT
A LITTLE PEPPER,
AND THEN WE PUT THE CORNED BEEF
IN AT THE LAST MINUTE.
BUT NOW WHAT IS THAT OVER THERE
ON THAT PART OF THE WALL?
I'M SORRY...
OH, THEY MOVED IT.
NEVER MIND.
ARE YOU READY
TO TASTE IT?
I'M READY TO ROCK.
MMM. SMELLS KILLER.
MMM.
THAT CORNED BEEF JUST
CARRIES ITS OWN FLAVOR,
AND THAT REALLY IS GOOD BEEF,
TOO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S GOOD BEEF.
THERE'S ENOUGH JUICE
GOING ON WITH IT,
I'M NOT EVEN LOOKIN'
FOR THE KETCHUP.
DO YOU WANT TO PUT A LITTLE
GREEN CHILE IN THERE?
OH, YEAH. I HOPE I'M NOT
BREAKING ANY, YOU KNOW,
RULES HERE IN
THE INTERNATIONAL BROTHERHOOD
OF CORNED BEEF LOVERS.
MMM. GREEN CHILE...
UH-HUH.
IS WHAT MAKES THAT.
MMM.
YOU CAN'T COME TO NEW MEXICO
AND NOT EAT OUR GREEN CHILE.
HEY, WHAT'S THAT
OVER THERE?
AND OFF HE GOES
WITH THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
HOW'S THE HASH TODAY?
IT'S GOOD.
I MIXED A LITTLE GREEN CHILE
INTO MINE AND OH.
OH.
AND THEY DO IT
REALLY WELL.
ARE MY GREEN ENCHILADAS
ALMOST READY?
EVERYTHING THAT I'VE HAD HERE
TASTES GREAT.
YOU HAVE
SUCH A VARIETY.
AND BETH'S ALWAYS THINKIN'
OF SOMETHING NEW.
WE JUST WANT TO KEEP
KIND OF UP IN THE GAME.
LIKE AN AHI TUNA SANDWICH
WITH MANGO SALSA,
GREEN CHILE EGGS BENEDICT
AND A TOTALLY FRESH TAKE...
CORN AND AVOCADO
GAZPACHO.
ON A COLD SUMMER CLASSIC...
IT'S LIKE COLD
GUACAMOLE SOUP.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY NICE.
ENJOY YOUR DINNER.
AT THE ZIA DINER
IN SANTA FE, NEW MEXICO...
WE'VE GOT ONE
SALMON QUESADILLA.
BETH DRAISCOL'S
DOING IT ALL HER WAY.
DINER AND ADOBE.
YEAH.
THERE'S OUR FISH-AND-CHIPS.
MIXIN' UP THE CLASSICS...
HOT TURKEY
WITH BROWN GRAVY.
WITH SOUTHWEST STANDARDS.
CHICKEN FAJITAS!
ONE OF MY FAVORITES IS
THE GREEN CHILE CHEESE FRIES.
MMM. WHERE'S THAT BEEN
ALL MY DIET?
AND FOR THE GAZPACHO,
SHE'S ONLY USING WHAT'S FRESH,
LOCAL AND IN SEASON.
AVOCADO CORN--
IT'S FABULOUS.
IT'S LIKE GUACAMOLE SOUP.
VERY, VERY GOOD.
IT'S A WONDERFUL
SUMMER SOUP.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE
ME A RUNDOWN.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME
YELLOW SQUASH AND ZUCCHINI,
RED BELL PEPPERS AND ONIONS,
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT THOSE
INTO THE ROBOT COUPE
AND PULSE THAT UP.
SO THAT'S YOUR TEXTURE.
AND THEN WE ADD
A BLANCHED CORN...
OKAY.
STRAIGHT FROM
THE FARMERS' MARKET YESTERDAY.
FINELY DICED
ROMAN TOMATOES, CILANTRO,
GARLIC,
SOME SERRANO CHILES.
GOTTA HAVE A LITTLE
HEAT IN THERE.
AND THEN WE PUT A BUNCH
OF CHOPPED AVOCADO.
A BIT ON
THE CHUNKIER SIDE.
YEP, LIME JUICE.
THIS TAKES QUITE A BIT OF SALT
'CAUSE THOSE AVOCADOES
ARE PRETTY MILD.
YEAH.
THERE'S NOTHING SALTY IN THERE.
WE'LL PUT A LITTLE PEPPER.
NOW WE JUST LET THAT
SIT THERE FOR A MINUTE
WHILE WE GO AHEAD
AND MAKE OUR AVOCADO PURéE.
SOME ICE WATER.
AND WHY THE ICE WATER?
WE JUST WANT IT TO BE COLD
THE MINUTE IT'S DONE.
YOU CAN SEE
THAT'S NICE AND THICK.
YOU HOLD, I'LL SCRAPE.
OKAY, AND NOW WE PUT
A BUNCH MORE WATER IN HERE,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA JUST WHISK
IT UP REALLY WELL.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TASTE IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
MMM. GET THE LEMON JUICE
RIGHT OFF THE TOP.
NICE MIX OF SEASONINGS.
THE CORN, THOUGH...
WE GET GOOD CORN
IN NORTHERN NEW MEXICO.
MMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE I LIKE,
IS THAT IT'S NOT SO COLD--
THAT YOU REALLY
CAN TASTE THE TOMATO--
EVERYBODY'S KIND OF
BRIGHT IN THERE.
YEAH.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY NICE.
I'M GONNA SIT HERE
AND FINISH THIS
BECAUSE THIS
IS REALLY GOOD.
IT'S FABULOUS.
YEAH, IT IS
PRETTY DYNAMITE.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
HOW'S DINNER TONIGHT?
OH, IT'S WONDERFUL.
GREAT STOP.
IT WAS VERY FRIENDLY.
GOT YOUR CHICKEN
HERE, KIDDO.
YOU ALWAYS
FEEL COMFORTABLE.
GOOD DOWN-HOME,
AMERICANA-TYPE FOOD.
AND LOTS
OF SANTA FE CUISINE.
YOU DON'T LOVE
WHAT YOU DO, DO YOU?
YEAH, I DO LOVE
WHAT I DO.
IT SHOWS.
HOW ARE YOU?
GREEN CHILE CHEESE FRIES.
SAY THAT FIVE TIMES FAST.
GREEN CHILE CHEESE FRIES,
GREEN CHILE CH-REE--
CHEESE FRIES.
OH!
DARN!
YOU HAD IT!
OH, YOU WERE SO CLOSE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LOOK AT THAT.
HUSH PUPPY.
(high-pitched voice) NEXT ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES..."
(laughter)