HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
WHAT I DO FOR YOU. MMM.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I THINK THERE'S SOME
IN MY EAR.
COMFORT COOKING
IN MILWAUKEE...
BACON APPLE PIE.
WHERE BACON'S A FOOD GROUP...
BANANA AND BACON?
SURE, WHY NOT?
GIVE ME SOME OF THAT
FRUIT PLATE.
FANTASTIC.
AND THIS IS TURKEY DINNER.
IT'S THANKSGIVING
IN CONVENIENT-TO-EAT
BALL FORM.
MMM. THAT GRAVY IS LEGIT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE BACON HAVEN,
GRAVY EMPORIUM.
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
(man) TABLE FIVE.
WHERE THEY'RE LINING UP...
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS FOOD.
FOR BREAKFAST DONE
THIS DUDE'S WAY.
I'M HAVING
THE BLACK BEAN CAKES.
IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S WHY I COME HERE.
THE CORN--LITTLE POPS IN THERE,
A LITTLE SWEETNESS. MMM.
MM-HMM.
TAKE THAT AWAY.
I'M STARTING TO EAT HEALTHY.
AND IN PHOENIX...
OUR FAVORITE
SUNDAY BREAKFAST PLACE.
WHERE A FRENCH-TRAINED CHEF...
SCRAMBLED HARD SOURDOUGH.
IS TAKIN' ON
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK...
SO DELICIOUS.
AND HAM WITH REDEYE GRAVY.
MMM, IT'S GONNA BE
A LITTLE BIT HARD TO ADMIT,
BUT THAT'S BETTER
THAN MY REDEYE GRAVY.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I THINK ONE
OF THE TAG LINES FOR TRIPLE "D"
SHOULD BE, "IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT."
HERE WE ARE ON THE EAST SIDE
OF MILWAUKEE.
NOW LAKE MICHIGAN'S
ABOUT TWO BLOCKS THAT WAY,
AND THE UNIVERSITY'S
ABOUT A MILE THAT WAY,
AND WE'RE AT A JOINT
THAT USED TO BE A COFFEE SHOP,
NOW TURNED INTO
A RESTAURANT AND A BAR.
NOW I KNOW YOU'RE SAYING,
"GUIDO,
WHERE'S THE FUNK IN THAT?"
HERE IT IS, FOLKS.
THIS PLACE IS A BACON HAVEN.
THEY HAVE BACON
IN THEIR BLOODY MARYS,
BACON ON THEIR APPLE PIE.
THEY HAVE BASKET-O-BACON
ON SUNDAYS.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS PLACE IS FUNK-A-LICIOUS.
WELCOME TO THE COMMON.
BACON APPLE PIE.
IT'S APPLE PIE
WITH BACON.
BLOODY MARY WITH BACON.
FOR A DOLLAR,
WE'LL PUT BACON FAT OR BACON IN
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING YOU ORDER.
FROM PANCAKES
AND BURGERS...
MANY OF MY FAVORITE
INGREDIENTS--BACON.
TO GOOD OLD AMERICAN
MAC AND CHEESE.
I HAVE YET TO FIND
A SINGLE FOOD
THAT DOESN'T
GO GOOD WITH BACON.
NOT SINCE TRAINED CHEF
ADAM LUCKS...
ORDER UP!
OPENED THIS JOINT
WITH HIS SISTER VAL...
EVERYTHING TASTE
ALL RIGHT SO FAR?
ABOUT FOUR YEARS AGO.
IT'S JUST YOU TWO WINGING IT
AND DOING IT YOUR WAY.
PRETTY MUCH.
ESSENTIALLY.
AHI TUNA!
EVEN FAVORITES
WITH NO BACON AT ALL.
A LEGHORN.
CHICKEN, PEACH JELLY ON TOP.
THE VEGAN GYRO.
VEGAN RUBEN TORTILLA.
FANTASTIC.
AND A HOMEMADE MEATLOAF
TOPPED WITH A BEER GRAVY
THAT TAKES THREE AND A HALF
DAYS TO MAKE.
LOT OF REDUCTION.
JUST OUT OF THIS WORLD.
WE'RE MAKING
THE BEER GRAVY.
BACON FAT.
YOU'RE STARTING OFF
THE RIGHT WAY.
WELL, OF COURSE.
A MIREPOIX.
CELERY, ONIONS
AND CARROTS.
YEP, AND THEN THE GARLIC.
COOKED DOWN.
WE'RE ACTUALLY LOOKING
FOR CARAMELIZATION ON THIS.
THAT'S WHERE YOU GET
THE RICHNESS IN THE GRAVY
IS ALL FROM THIS VEG
RIGHT HERE.
OKAY, SO WE HAVE A NICE
LITTLE CARAMELIZATION.
TOMATO PASTE GOES NEXT,
AND THEN WE'LL ADD THE BEER.
OKAY.
THIS IS A MILD ALE.
THEN WE ADD SOME RED WINE.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE ADD
THE HERBS--
PARSLEY, FRESH ROSEMARY,
THYME, SOME BAY LEAVES
AND ABOUT FIVE GALLONS
OF BEEF STOCK.
THE BEEF STOCK
YOU MAKE YOURSELF.
YEAH, BEEF BONES, HERBS,
BLACK PEPPERCORNS,
RED WINE AND WATER.
AND IF THE KITCHEN SINK
WEREN'T BOLTED TO THE WALL,
WE'D ADD
THE KITCHEN SINK, TOO.
WHY NOT?
THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT OUT,
PUT IT INTO ANOTHER POT,
AND WE'RE GONNA
REDUCE IT AGAIN.
AND THIS IS JUST
FOR TWO DISHES?
TWO DISHES--MEATLOAF SANDWICH
AND THE MEATLOAF ENTRéE.
MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
THE WAY THAT I THINK MOM
WOULD MAKE IT,
IF MOM KNEW
HOW TO COOK.
SO WE'RE MAKING
THE MEATLOAF--
MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
WISCONSIN-RAISED, GRASS-FED
BEEF. REALLY GREAT STUFF.
OKAY.
GREEN PEPPERS, RED PEPPERS,
WHITE ONION.
ROCKY BALBOA MILKSHAKE.
WHOLE BUNCH
OF EGGS THERE.
FRESH MINT, SAGE,
GARLIC, BREAD CRUMBS.
LET ME ASK--
DO YOU MAKE 'EM YOURSELF?
OF COURSE.
WHO WOULDN'T MAKE THEIR--
WHY PAY FOR BREAD CRUMBS?
EXACTLY, EXACTLY.
ALL RIGHT, THEN MY FAVORITE
INGREDIENT--BACON FAT.
SOME KETCHUP.
WHO'S RECIPE WAS THIS?
KIND OF A HYBRID OF MY RECIPE
AND MY MOM'S RECIPE.
AND HERE'S ACTUALLY
WHERE MOM COMES INTO PLAY.
USES THE ONION SOUP MIX.
THIS IS THE ONION
SOUP MIX.
KICKER.
SHE SAID I ABSOLUTELY
HAVE TO USE THIS.
ALL RIGHT, SALT AND PEPPER,
AND THEN JUST FOR GOOD MEASURE,
YOU GOTTA HAVE BUTTER
IN EVERYTHING.
SO NOW IT GOES
TO THE MIXER.
YOU DON'T OVERMIX
THIS, CORRECT?
NOPE, JUST TILL
ITS COMBINED.
AND THEN WHAT ARE WE
BAKING THIS BAD BOY IN?
PULLMAN LOAF PAN.
GET SOME BIG OL'
SWEET BACON FAT.
(speaking indistinctly)
THIS IS LIKE THE GLUE FOR
THE BACON THAT LINES THE PAN.
BACON STRIPS.
WOW.
THIS IS THICK-CUT BACON, MAN.
ONLY WAY YOU COULD
GET THAT THICKER
IS IF YOU SHOVED A PIG
IN THERE YOURSELF.
WHICH, YOU KNOW WHAT,
SOMEDAY I MIGHT TRY THAT.
TAKE THE MEAT MIXTURE,
YOU GOTTA PACK IT IN THERE
REAL GOOD. THERE YOU GO.
NOW HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
BAKE THAT OFF FOR?
ABOUT 35 MINUTES.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'LL PULL IT OUT,
WE'LL PUT A NICE SLATHERING
OF KETCHUP ON TOP--
'CAUSE YOU HAVE
TO DO THAT.
OH, THAT'S MOM.
YEAH, ONION SOUP
AND KETCHUP. OKAY.
MM-HMM. AND THEN WE'LL BAKE IT
FOR ABOUT ANOTHER 15 MINUTES
JUST TO BROWN IT UP, AND THEN
YOU GOTTA LET IT COOL OVERNIGHT.
(whistles)
AND THEN I'LL JUST
TIP IT UP ON END.
OH, AND THEN
WE SQUEEZE IT OUT.
IT'S FIGHTING ME
A LITTLE BIT.
COME ON, BUDDY.
THERE WE GO.
(imitates baby crying)
SPANK IT!
AND THERE--
(laughs) SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
HEAT IT BACK UP?
YEP, RIGHT IN THE BUTTER.
PUT A LITTLE CRISP
ON BOTH SIDES.
SOME SALTED RYE BREAD,
ONIONS, MORE BUTTER,
COUPLE SLICES OF TOMATO,
RYE BREAD ON THE PLATE,
MOUNTAIN OF MEATLOAF,
BACON CHIVE MASHED POTATOES,
AND OUR BEER GRAVY--
WE DON'T WANT TO SKIMP ON THIS.
NO, WE DON'T.
A COUPLE STRIPS OF BACON
RIGHT OVER THE TOP OF THERE.
TOMATOES OVER,
ONIONS ON TOP OF THAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY.
THERE YOU GO.
MEAT MOUNTAIN.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
HOW TO ATTACK IT.
GO UP THE NORTH BASE,
COME AROUND THROUGH THE CANYON?
EVERYBODY HAS
THEIR OWN STYLE.
HUH.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO TELL YOU.
I THINK YOU'RE DANGEROUS, OKAY?
AND I LIKE THAT. THAT'S KILLER.
THIS
IS YOUR CULINARY ADVENTURE,
AND THIS
IS YOUR TOUR GUIDE.
MEATLOAF'S GOING
IN THE WINDOW.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR A COMFORT
MEAL, THAT WOULD DO IT.
MAYBE MORE BACON.
MORE BACON?
I DIDN'T REALIZE
THEY DID SO MUCH WITH BACON.
BANANA AND BACON?
SURE, WHY NOT?
HEY, GIVE ME SOME
OF THAT FRUIT PLATE.
THEY'RE EVEN GIVING IT AWAY
ON SUNDAY NIGHTS--
HERE IS YOUR BACON.
ALL YOU WANT
IF YOU BUY A BEER.
BOTTOMLESS BACON?
YEAH, ALL YOU CAN EAT.
AND THEN SOME.
THE AKIMBO BURGER.
IT'S QUITE DELICIOUS.
IT IS WEDGED BETWEEN
TWO GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICHES.
WHAT IS ALL THIS?
GRILLED CHEESE,
LETTUCE, TOMATO,
THEN THE BURGER.
THAT'S WHERE MOST PEOPLE
WOULD JUST CALL IT QUITS.
THEN WE'LL ADD THE FRIED EGG,
SWEET BABY SHAY'S SECRET SAUCE,
BACON, MUSHROOMS,
ONION RINGS, JALAPEñO RELISH,
THE OTHER GRILLED CHEESE
AND THE SKEWER.
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT.
THAT IS THE AKIMBO BURGER.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WHAT I DO FOR YOU.
I THINK THERE'S SOME
IN MY EAR. MMM.
THAT'S SOME
KIND OF BURGER.
ALL MY FAVORITES IN ONE.
IT'S LIKE MY BIRTHDAY.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
RECREATE IT AT HOME.
IT'S THINGS YOU KNOW
IN KIND OF A DIFFERENT WAY.
LIKE SOMETHING
THEY NAMED AFTER A BUDDY--
A.J.'s COMPACT TURKEY DINNER.
MMM.
IT'S THANKSGIVING IN
CONVENIENT-TO-EAT BALL FORM.
KILLER STUFFING,
MASHED POTATOES
AND FRESH,
ROASTED TURKEY BREAST.
YEP, AND YOU JUST GET IN
AND MIX IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE 'EM
INTO LITTLE BALLS,
THEN WE'LL FLOUR 'EM,
BEER BATTER 'EM.
NOW HOW DO YOU MAKE
THE BEER BATTER?
FLOUR AND BEER
AND SALT AND PEPPER.
THROW 'EM
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
THEY'RE GONNA GET SERVED IN
A CHICKEN GRAVY THAT WE MADE.
PLACE THE TURKEY RIGHT THERE
IN THE CENTER OF THE GRAVY.
A LITTLE PARSLEY FOR COLOR,
AND THERE YOU GO.
HMM. THAT GRAVY IS LEGIT.
SEE, THIS IS THE COMPONENT
THAT WE'RE MISSING
IN THANKSGIVING IS CRUNCH.
THIS IS CRUNCH-A-TASTICAL.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THE BACON HAVEN,
GRAVY EMPORIUM.
GET JUST ABOUT ANYTHING OFF
THE MENU, AND IT'S REALLY GREAT.
ALWAYS TASTES DELICIOUS.
AKIMBO BURGER, ORDER UP!
I THINK IT'S FANTASTIC.
LUCKY YOU HAVE HER
KEEPING YOU IN LINE.
SHE DOES.
HE'S OUTTA CONTROL.
SOMEONE'S GOTTA
BOSS HIM AROUND.
BACON PUSHER.
UP NEXT...
ZUCCHINI CAKES.
WE'RE HEADING WEST...
THE BEST BREAKFAST
I'VE HAD IN SAN FRANCISCO.
FOR JALAPEñO CORN BREAD...
OH. SMELL THIS.
AND HOMEMADE JELLY.
PRETTY OUT OF BOUNDS.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
I'M IN SAN FRANCISCO.
NOW, I'M A NOR CAL BOY,
SO ANY CHANCE I GET
TO SHOOT CLOSE TO HOME, I DO.
SAN FRANCISCO, LIKE ANY CITY,
HAS ITS UNIQUE AREAS,
AND TODAY I'M IN AN AREA
CALLED THE TENDERLOIN DISTRICT
AT A PLACE CALLED
DOTTIE'S TRUE BLUE CAFE,
WHERE PEOPLE
WILL WAIT UP TO AN HOUR
TO GET 1 OF THE 40 SEATS.
GOOD MORNING. DOTTIE'S. YES,
THERE IS A WAIT AT THE MOMENT.
THIS IS EVERY MORNING?
EVERY MORNING.
DOES ANYBODY
SCALP TICKETS?
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
THE BEST BREAKFAST
I'VE HAD IN SAN FRANCISCO.
ZUCCHINI CAKE.
THEY MAKE
EVERYTHING FRESH.
HERE WE GO--
THE FRITTATA.
(man) I TRY TO GIVE THE BEST
QUALITY THAT I POSSIBLY CAN.
AND KURT ABNEY'S
BEEN ROLLING THAT WAY
SINCE HE BOUGHT THIS JOINT
16 YEARS AGO.
ONE MINUTE
ON THE POACH.
I HAD NEVER DONE BREAKFAST.
TABLE FIVE.
NOPE--KURT WENT
TO PASTRY SCHOOL.
THIS PLACE WAS FOR SALE.
I THOUGHT I'D GIVE IT A TRY
AND PUT MY OWN SLANT ON IT.
ROASTED PUMPKIN OAT PANCAKES--
THEY'RE ALWAYS REALLY GOOD.
THE LAMB AND GOAT CHEESE
OMELET--IT'S AWESOME.
CORN BREAD, STRAIGHT UP--
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I LIKE
TO CONSTANTLY EXPERIMENT.
LIKE SERVING THAT CORN BREAD
WITH SCRATCH-MADE
JALAPEñO JELLY.
CORN BREAD ON THE SIDE.
OKAY,
LET'S GET 'ER GOING.
WE START WITH
UNBLEACHED FLOUR HERE.
CORNMEAL.
BAKING POWDER,
SALT, SUGAR.
A CUP OF JALAPEñO PEPPERS
CHOPPED UP.
FRESH?
FRESH.
CHOPPED GREEN ONION,
4 CUPS OF NEW YORK
SHARP CHEDDAR CHEESE.
TEN EGGS, OLIVE OIL,
HALF A GALLON
OF BUTTERMILK.
CHUG-A-LUG, CHUG-A-LUG.
WE HAVE THAT
ALL MIXED UP.
GETTIN' SMACKED
IN THE HEAD WITH THAT. WHACK.
DOES THIS PROOF
BEFORE IT GOES IN?
NO.
SO IT'S GONNA DO ALL
ITS LEAVENING IN THE HEAT.
RIGHT.
OKAY, 400 DEGREES.
HOW LONG?
AN HOUR.
AN HOUR--
REALLY? THAT LONG?
SO THEY'VE COOLED DOWN,
AND NOW YOU POP 'EM OUT.
LOOKS LIKE A FULL-BLOWN BARGE
GOING TO FLAVOR TOWN.
OH.
SO IT SMELLS LIKE
THE JALAPEñO AND THE CHEESE.
YOU GOT THE LITTLE NUGGETS
OF THE JALAPEñO AND THE ONIONS.
SMELL THIS.
SO WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
WE PUT A LITTLE BUTTER ON IT
AND GRILL IT?
YES.
I MEAN, I'VE SEEN CORN BREAD
DONE A LOT OF WAYS,
BUT I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'VE BEEN
TO THE GRIDDLING O' CORN BREAD
SCHOOL.
THIS GONNA GET SERVED WITH
THE JALAPEñO JELLY YOU MADE?
AND WHAT'S IN IT?
IT HAS RED AND GREEN
BELL PEPPERS,
CHOPPED JALAPEñO,
CHIPOTLE PEPPER,
CALCIUM WATER,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
THE PECTIN, THE SUGAR.
PEOPLE LOVE
THE JELLY ON IT.
MMM. THERE'S A CONTRAST.
COLD, SWEET AND SOUR,
JALAPEñO JELLY
WITH HOT, WARM,
CRUNCHY CORN BREAD.
MMM. GET JUST A HINT
OF THE CHEESE IN THERE.
PRETTY OUT OF BOUNDS.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
IT IS OUTSTANDING.
IT'S THE PERFECT PAIR,
DON'T YOU THINK?
PERFECT.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
THE FRESHEST FOOD
YOU CAN EVER EAT.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO ME
THAT IF I MADE IT,
I WANT TO KNOW
WHAT'S IN IT.
SO HE'S ON THE GRILL HIMSELF
250 MEALS A DAY.
TABLE NINE.
WITH JUST
ONE OTHER COOK.
IT'S OSCAR AND I BACK HERE.
JUST THE TWO OF YOU?
WE MOVE AS FAST
AS WE CAN.
YOU GUYS DO MOVE FAST.
THE BAKERY GOODS
THEY MAKE THAT MORNING.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT--
YOU BAKE ALL THIS?
EVERYTHING YOU SEE THERE
WAS MADE HERE.
MUFFINS, SCONES,
CINNAMON ROLLS, TARTS.
TWO KINDS OF BREAD--
WHOLE WHEAT, BUTTERMILK DILL.
BUTTERMILK WHAT?
DILL.
OH, I HAVE GOTTA TRY
BUTTERMILK DILL.
THAT'S OUR STANDARD
TOAST BREAD.
IT'S GREAT BY ITSELF.
THAT'S BIG BREAD.
WE LIKE BIG FOOD HERE.
TINY PLACE...
(imitates boat horn)
BIG FOOD.
I HAVE A FRITTATA.
THERE'S AVOCADO, TOMATO, CORN,
JALAPEñO. IT'S DELICIOUS.
I LIKE THAT THEY CATER
TO VEGETARIANS.
WITH FAVORITES
LIKE VEGGIE CHILI...
GREAT CHILI.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
SCRATCH-MADE
FROM KURT'S OWN RECIPE.
LET'S GET THE PARTY
STARTED HERE.
ADD A LITTLE OIL
IN HERE.
SO WE GOT ONION,
RED AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
A LITTLE FRESH CORN.
A LOT OF GARLIC
IN THERE.
WHOA, BATMAN.
SO THE DRIED BEANS
SOAKED OVERNIGHT
THAT WE'VE HAD SITTING THERE
SIMMERING IN THE WATER--
THEY'RE ALMOST DONE?
YES.
OKAY.
ZUCCHINI AND CARROTS.
YOU DON'T SEE THAT
IN EVERY CHILI.
DUMP THOSE RIGHT
INTO THE BEANS.
JALAPEñO.
MY POT'S STARTING TO BECOME,
LIKE, THE OVERFLOW POT.
YOU HAVE
THE BIG, EASY ONE.
RIGHT.
WE DO SOME
ROASTED GARLIC, TOO.
AS YOU SHOULD.
CHILI POWDER.
DARK AND A LIGHT.
BOTH OF THOSE
WERE CHILI POWDER?
YEAH.
A LITTLE CUMIN--
A LOT OF CUMIN.
RAW GARLIC, ROASTED GARLIC,
GARLIC POWDER--I LIKE THIS.
CAYENNE, OREGANO.
DO I SEE CHIPOTLE
WITH ADOBO?
YOU DO.
AHA!
SALT AND PEPPER.
THAT IS THICK CHILI.
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR
AND SOME
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
MMM, LITTLE BITE THERE.
GO AHEAD AND TOSS IT
IN HERE NOW.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IN
SOME CILANTRO.
SO YOU JUST LET THIS SIT HERE
AND CONTINUE TO SIMMER
A LITTLE BIT LONGER?
YES.
WOW, THAT'S AWESOME.
WE MAY AS WELL THROW
A LITTLE CHEESE ON TOP, TOO...
OH, MAN.
IF YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE SOME CHILI.
MMM. THERE'S SO MANY
COMPLEXITIES TO THE CHILI,
ESPECIALLY
THE VEGGIES IN IT.
MM-HMM.
MMM. WOW.
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
ON THE CORN BREAD,
OR IN ONE OF THESE.
I'M HAVING
THE BLACK BEAN CAKES.
IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S WHY I COME HERE.
SO THE CHILI THAT WE MADE
GOES INTO THIS ALSO?
YES.
WE'LL GRAB ABOUT FOUR SCOOPS
OF THIS OUT OF HERE
AND THEN PUT IT
IN HERE.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SIZE
DOWN ON THIS...
RIGHT.
PURéEING IT A BIT.
TOSS THIS IN HERE.
BROWN RICE.
GREAT TEXTURE.
MULTIPLE BREADS
OF BREAD CRUMBS.
SO BECAUSE OF THE WAY
YOU TREATED THE CHILI,
IT'S GONNA HAVE ENOUGH
BINDER IN ITSELF...
YES.
TO TIGHTEN THIS UP?
PUT THAT IN A CONE.
SO THESE GET GRILLED UP?
THESE ARE READY.
THEY'RE NICE AND CRISPY.
SOUR CREAM.
SOME PICO DE GALLO.
MMM. (laughs)
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING
ABOUT RIGHT THERE. MMM.
THE CORN--LITTLE POPS IN THERE,
A LITTLE SWEETNESS.
THE BROWN RICE--FIRST--
IT'S WHAT'S IN MY TEETH
RIGHT NOW.
MMM. TAKE THAT AWAY.
I'M STARTING TO EAT HEALTHY.
WINNER, WINNER,
BEAN PATTY DINNER.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S WORTH THE WAIT.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS FOOD.
HAD THE MOST
FANTASTIC BREAKFAST
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
(Kurt) TABLE FIVE.
EVERYBODY LOVES IT.
IF YOU SIT DOWN
AND YOU EAT IT, YOU KNOW.
THAT'S WHY YOU WAIT
IN LINE.
I'D DRIVE UP HERE,
DROP MY SON HUNTER OFF,
MAKE HIM WAIT IN LINE
FOR AN HOUR--
WELL, PEOPLE
DO THAT, TOO.
OH, DO THEY REALLY?
THAT'S A--YEAH.
NEXT STOP...
IT'S FABULOUS.
ARIZONA...
2-EGG BREAKFAST.
FOR--YEAH,
SOME BREAKFAST BASICS.
(man) BANANA CARAMEL SAUCE,
TOASTED PECANS.
MMM. THAT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
WHEN I THINK
OF PHOENIX, ARIZONA,
I THINK ABOUT BREAKFAST.
NOW I THINK THAT'S BECAUSE
PEOPLE GET UP EARLY
TO START THEIR DAY
BEFORE IT HITS 100.
NOW LAST TIME WE WERE HERE,
WE FOUND MATT'S BIG BREAKFAST,
AND, OH, IT WAS OFF THE HOOK.
THIS TIME, IT'S A NEW PLACE,
AND WHAT USED TO BE
A FAST FOOD TACO JOINT
IS NOW CALLED OVER EASY,
WHERE DOING A QUALITY BREAKFAST
IS REALLY THEIR THING.
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
WITH AN OVER-EASY EGG.
SO DELICIOUS.
OUR FAVORITE
SUNDAY BREAKFAST PLACE.
IT'S FABULOUS.
I LOVE IT.
REALLY?
I LOVE PLACES LIKE THIS
THAT HAVE MORE OF
THE HEARTY BREAKFAST FOOD.
IT'S DINER FOOD.
IT'S THAT LOCAL MIDWEST
KIND OF FEEL TO THE PLACE.
SCRAMBLED HARD SOURDOUGH.
AND CHEF AARON MAY
MIGHT HAVE TRAINED ALL OVER...
HERE, PARIS, NEW YORK.
BUT HIS ROOTS
ARE PURE MIDWEST.
YOU'RE FROM CHICAGO.
FROM CHICAGO.
YOU COME TO PHOENIX
BECAUSE...
YOU DON'T HAVE
TO SHOVEL SUNSHINE.
(laughs)
BUT YOU DO
NEED A PLACE TO EAT.
KIND OF OPENED IT
JUST FOR OURSELVES
TO HAVE A PLACE TO GO
EAT BREAKFAST. FOR YOU.
IT'S OLD SCHOOL.
FRENCH TOAST
AND TWO EGGS SUNNY-SIDE UP,
AND THEY ARE AWESOME.
I HAVE
THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
DELECTABLE.
REDEYE GRAVY AND HAM--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S THE GRAVY ON THE HAM STEAK
THAT REALLY MAKES IT HERE.
WE'RE MAKING SOME CHICKEN STOCK
THAT'S GONNA GO TO?
CHICKEN JUS, AND THEN
BECOME REDEYE GRAVY.
THIS IS LIKE REDEYE GRAVY
GONE WILD.
YEAH, NEXT STEP.
WE'RE GONNA BRING
A WHOLE CHICKEN
AND SOME EXTRA CHICKEN BACKS
THAT I GOT LAYING AROUND.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE AN EXTRA
CHICKEN BACK LAYING AROUND.
I'M GONNA COVER THAT
WITH COLD WATER.
SO IT'S KIND OF LIKE
AN ALASKAN CHICKEN HOT TUB.
THERE YOU GO.
GONNA ADD ONIONS, GOOD AMOUNT
OF CARROTS AND CELERY.
I'VE GOT SOME PARSLEY STEMS.
'CAUSE THERE'S A LOT OF
FLAVOR COMING OUT OF THOSE.
I'VE GOT THYME.
ON YOUR MIND.
ON MY SIDE.
♪ DA DA DA ♪
PEPPERCORNS.
SO WE'RE GONNA LET THIS
SIT HERE AND SIMMER FOR...
TWO HOURS.
NOW WE'RE ON TO PART TWO--
THE CHICKEN JUS.
I'M GONNA TAKE THE CHICKEN,
AND I'M GONNA ADD IT
TO THE BUTTER--CHICKEN WINGS,
CHICKEN DRUMETTES.
THIS IS WHERE
THE CHICKEN BACK CAME FROM.
THEN I'M GONNA COOK IT DOWN,
I'M GONNA LET IT BROWN.
AND I GOT SOME WHITE ONION
TO ADD TO THAT.
NOW I'M GONNA COVER IT WITH
CHICKEN STOCK THAT WE MADE.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
THIS LITTLE TECHNIQUE?
THIS IS SOMETHING, YOU KNOW,
OLD-SCHOOL EUROPEAN.
THIS IS MY RIGHT-HAND GUY
WALLY'S WAY TO MAKE CHICKEN JUS.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL. AS SOON
AS THIS REDUCES...
THAT TAKES US
AN HOUR OR SO.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT.
STRAIN IT.
(inhales sharply)
IS THAT CHICKEN-RIFIC,
OR WHAT, MAN?
I'VE HAD PORK-TASTIC,
BUT THAT'S CHICKEN-RIFIC.
ADD THE COFFEE TO IT,
AND REDUCE THAT
UNTIL IT'S THICK
AND GRAVY-LIKE.
ALL OF THAT FOR A SAUCE
FOR HAM STEAK.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S GOOD.
A DELICIOUS SAUCE
FOR A HAM STEAK.
THIS GUY--OUT OF BOUNDS.
HAM STEAK GOES FLAT TOP.
PUT THAT DOWN
ON THE FLAT TOP.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
AND WHAT DO WE SERVE ON
THE HIGH SIDE OF THE HAM STEAK?
POTATOES--NICE HASH BROWNS.
THAT HAM STEAK ON THERE.
SOME OF THAT REDEYE GRAVY.
DON'T BE SHY WITH THAT.
OH, I'M NOT GOING TO.
MMM.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
THAT REALLY HAS SOME DEPTH.
THAT'S LIKE A SAUCE.
YEAH, YOU GET
ANOTHER DIMENSION.
IT'S GONNA BE A LITTLE BIT
HARD TO ADMIT,
BUT THAT'S BETTER
THAN MY REDEYE GRAVY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
OH, IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THREE EGGS,
STEAK AND CHILI.
GOT IT.
THE MENU IS VERY UNIQUE,
AND THEY HAVE SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE.
2-EGG BREAKFAST.
EGGS, HASH BROWN, BACON.
BACON'S DELICIOUS HERE.
'CAUSE AARON'S TAKEN
THE EXTRA STEPS TO BRING IN
WHAT HE LOVES.
BACON FROM WISCONSIN.
SAUSAGE THAT'S
MADE LOCALLY.
(speaking indistinctly)
AND THE TIME TO MAKE ALMOST
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
BAKING OUR OWN SCONES,
THE WHOLE NINE YARDS.
BLUEBERRY MUFFINS
WITH THE LEMON CURD.
SO IT'S THE REAL DEAL HERE?
WE THINK SO.
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
COMING UP.
MAKE OUR OWN CHICKEN-FRIED
STEAK, WE MAKE OUR OWN GRAVY.
WE TAKE A LOT OF PRIDE IN
DOING ALL OF THAT FROM SCRATCH.
REALLY GOOD,
REAL JUICY.
WE'RE MAKING COUNTRY GRAVY
FOR THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
SO I'M GONNA START
WITH A LITTLE BUTTER.
DUMP THAT BACON IN THERE.
HE'S TRYING TO GIVE ME
DIET PLATE OR SOMETHING.
THIS IS SOME OF OUR CHOPPED-UP
BREAKFAST SAUSAGE.
YOU PUT A LITTLE MORE
CRISP ON THAT BACON,
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH SOME FLOUR?
EXACTLY.
COOK THAT OUT A LITTLE BIT,
ADD A LITTLE MILK.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT
COME UP TO A BOIL.
YOU DON'T MAKE YOURS
VERY TIGHT.
NO, WE DON'T MAKE IT
SUPER TIGHT AT ALL.
AND THEN WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA SEASON IT WITH?
SALT AND PEPPER AND I'M GONNA
ADD FRESH HERBS--
CHIVES AND PARSLEY.
BUTTER, BACON, SAUSAGE,
FLOUR, MILK--
A CHICKEN-FRIED FLIP-FLOP
WOULD BE FINE WITH THAT ON IT.
YUM. YUM. OKAY, NOW LET'S DO
THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
GRANULATED GARLIC...
CUMIN.
...A LITTLE CAYENNE,
HUNGARIAN PAPRIKA.
OOH, SO YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF SPICE ON IT.
ONION POWDER--
REALLY GOOD.
ONION.
REALLY NICE.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
SEASON IT UP
WITH A LITTLE SALT
AND THEN FLOUR.
BOY, THAT'S GONNA BE
A PRETTY BOUNTIFUL SEASONING.
YEAH. SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
POUND OUT A STEAK.
THIS IS CUBE STEAK.
LIGHTLY, GINGERLY...
THERE--IT'S NICE AND THIN.
LET'S MAKE A LITTLE EGG WASH.
A LITTLE MILK,
SALT AND PEPPER.
I LOVE YOUR
PRECISE MEASURING.
IT'S VERY, VERY PRECISE
OVER HERE.
A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT AND PEPPER.
DREDGE IT IN
THE SEASONED FLOUR.
FLOUR STICKS
TO THE WET MEAT,
THE EGG WASH
STICKS TO THE FLOUR,
AND THEN THE FLOUR
STICKS TO THE EGG WASH
THAT WAS STICKING
TO THE WET MEAT
THAT LIVES IN THE HOUSE
THAT AARON BUILT.
DROP IT RIGHT
IN THE FRYER.
350 DEGREES, CANOLA OIL.
CRAZY TASTY.
HOOK THAT UP WITH AN EGG.
HASH BROWNS DOWN.
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK
RIGHT ON TOP OF THAT.
GET A LITTLE EGG
RIGHT THERE FOR YOU,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
GO FOR THE GRAVY.
THERE YOU GO.
HERE'S A LITTLE
HOMEMADE TOMATO JAM
TO GO WITH
THOSE POTATOES.
MMM. IT DOESN'T LACK
IN FLAVOR.
IT REALLY DOESN'T. I THINK
THE FRIED STEAK IS DYNAMITE.
MMM. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S TENDER.
SUPER TENDER.
MMM. HANG ON A SECOND.
THE HASH BROWNS WITH SOME
OF THAT TOMATO RELISH--
THIS IS JUST OUT OF BOUNDS
RIGHT HERE.
MMM. OKAY.
(mumbling)
THE GRAVY--
IT COMPLEMENTED IT,
SO IT MADE EVERYTHING
JUST THAT MUCH BETTER.
VERY, VERY GOOD.
THEY HAVE REALLY UNIQUE FOOD
ON THEIR MENU.
LIKE FRENCH TOAST
MADE WITH BRIOCHE.
BANANA PECAN CARAMEL
FRENCH TOAST.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS BANANA.
REALLY,
THERE'S BANANAS IN IT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
BANANAS IS GOOD.
CHOCOLATE WAFFLES.
AT OVER EASY
IN PHOENIX, ARIZONA...
I NEED TWO EGGS OVER HARD
WITH BACON AND WHEAT TOAST.
AARON MAY IS DISHING OUT
THE COMFORT FOOD.
YOU GOT A HAM STEAK
WITH GRAVY ON THE SIDE.
ANYTHING I SHOULD TRY
FIRST TIME I COME HERE?
(man) WOLF PACK.
WOLF PACK.
HASH BROWNS, BACON, EGG
OF CHOICE, CHEESE OF CHOICE,
HASH BROWNS--
CAN'T GO WRONG.
IT'S THAT ONE-OF-A-KIND PLACE.
AND THIS PARIS-TRAINED CHEF...
I NEED
A BANANA FRENCH TOAST.
IS GIVING HIS FRENCH TOAST
A FRENCH TWIST
BY MAKING IT
WITH BRIOCHE.
OH, I WANNA TRY
A PIECE OF THIS.
ABSOLUTELY.
MMM. WHO MAKES THIS
FOR YOU?
A GUY NAMED M.J.
RIGHT DOWN THE ROAD.
MAKES ALL THE BREAD HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
HOW BIG?
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
SEE THAT? THAT'S A 90, BABY.
THAT'S HOW THEY WOULD CHECK IT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A CARAMEL SAUCE NOW.
OKAY.
BANANA CARAMEL SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT.
HEAVY PAN--
PUT MY SUGAR IN THERE.
WANT SOME HEAT?
YEAH, A LITTLE HEAT. JUST
START MELTIN' THAT SUGAR DOWN.
SO HERE YOU GO.
IT'S STARTING TO MELT.
TURNING INTO CARAMEL, BASICALLY,
SO I'M GONNA TURN THAT HEAT OFF.
WE'RE GONNA
WHISK IN SOME CREAM.
"WHISK" CREAM YOU WANT,
THIS ONE?
THAT'S PERFECT.
POUR THAT IN,
I'LL START WHISKING.
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S LOOKIN' GOOD.
KEEP GOIN'. PERFECT.
GONNA ADD A TINY BIT OF BUTTER,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
HELP THAT CARAMEL
REALLY STAND OUT.
THAT'S REALLY ONE
OF MY FAVORITE THINGS--
YEAH.
THE SALT AND CARAMEL.
THEN I'M JUST GONNA
TAKE SOME SLICED BANANAS.
LET THE CARAMEL SAUCE
BRING THOSE UP TO TEMP.
EXACTLY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
EGG WASH FOR THE FRENCH TOAST.
DIG IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM
IN THERE, A LITTLE CINNAMON.
CINNAMON-AMON-AMON-AMON.
I'VE GOT A COUPLE VANILLA BEANS
THAT I SPLIT.
MADAGASCARIAN.
YES.
AS FAR AS I KNOW.
WHIP THIS UP, GET THIS
SOFT-BEAT WHIPPED CREAM
GOING INTO THE EGG,
BREAK UP THE VANILLA BEANS.
NOW IS IT A LITTLE
DUNK, DUNK, GRIDDLE?
EXACTLY.
DUNK, DUNK, AND THEN
OVER TO THE GRIDDLE.
IS THIS A BIG SELLER HERE?
THIS IS A HUGE SELLER.
PEOPLE LOVE THIS ONE.
WE'RE DONE.
(whistles)
WE'VE GOT
OUR BANANA CARAMEL SAUCE.
FINISH THAT WITH
SOME TOASTED PECANS
AND A LITTLE... SUGAR.
'CAUSE WE NEED MORE.
THAT'S GONNA BE STRAIGHT
DELICIOUS RIGHT THERE, GUY.
WELL, SEE,
YOU'RE TALKING TO A GUY
THAT'S NOT A HUGE SWEETS FAN,
BUT WHAT'S SAVING IT
IS THE SALT IN THE CARAMEL.
YOU HAD ME AT HELLO THERE.
MMM.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
THIS IS CRAZY.
THE BRIOCHE--I JUST GOTTA
SHOW THE CAMERA. LOOK AT THAT.
THE PERFECT BITE.
AWESOME.
THIS REALLY IS BANANAS.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
JUST LUSCIOUS, REALLY SWEET.
COMBINATION
I'VE NEVER HAD BEFORE.
ENJOY, GUYS.
IT'S JUST REALLY FRESH,
HOMEMADE.
I LIKE THE ATMOSPHERE,
AND IT'S NICE AND HOMEY.
HAVE YOU ALL
BEEN HERE BEFORE?
YES, MANY TIMES.
MANY, MANY, MANY,
MANY TIMES.
I LOVE IT. IT'S GREAT.
IT'S REALLY BEEN A LOT OF FUN.
YOU'RE AWESOME.
GREAT JOB.
SO I TOLD YOU,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
PUT 'EM UP LIKE THIS--
JAZZ HANDS.
SHAKE 'EM.
♪ JAZZ HANDS ♪
AND HE THREW
A LITTLE RHYTHM TO IT.
♪ JAZZ HANDS ♪