I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
IT'S A PLACE
THAT EVERYBODY COMES.
GO-TO JOINTS...
HOW ARE YOU DOIN'?
IN PORTLAND...
HERE WE GO.
THE FAMILY FAVORITE
WHERE THEY'RE MAKIN'
THEIR OWN HOT DOGS...
HA HA!
AND 50
OTHER KINDS OF SAUSAGE.
BRATS, GERMAN LINKS, CHICKEN.
AND PULL UP A CHAIR...
THERE'S THE OLD-FASHIONED.
'CAUSE THEY'RE GRILLIN'
ON THE SIDEWALK...
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
YOU THE MAN.
IN SAN RAFAEL, CALIFORNIA...
JUST DELICIOUS.
WHERE "SOL FOOD"
AT THIS JOINT...
THIS IS AUTHENTIC.
MEANS PUERTO RICAN LASAGNA...
MMM.
AND A NEW TAKE ON STEAK...
BISTEC SANDWICH--DELICIOUS.
MEAT'S NICE AND TENDER. MMM.
YOU'LL LOVE THE BISTEC.
AND IN CONNECTICUT...
PICK UP STEAMERS.
THE BEACHED BARGE...
IT'S ORIGINAL.
WITH A BIG-DEAL BURGER...
TONS OF FLAVOR.
DO YOU STUFF BRIE CHEESE
IN A BURGER?
YES.
AND REAL
NEW ENGLAND SEAFOOD.
MMM. UH-HUH.
I'M GONNA EAT ALL OF 'EM.
MMM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
WE'VE SEEN LOTS OF THINGS
MADE BY HAND
HERE ON TRIPLE "D"--
BREAD, BAGELS, TORTILLAS,
EVEN THE TURDUCKEN.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS
WE'VE NEVER SEEN--
SOMETHING WE ALL LOVE
AND ADMIRE--
THE KID-PLEASING, GRILL-LOVING,
OLD-FASHIONED HOTDOG.
SO THAT BRINGS US HERE
TO PORTLAND, OREGON,
TO THE FOURTH-GENERATION
SAUSAGE KITCHEN AT OTTO'S.
HOLY MOLY!
IT'S LIKE MEAT DISNEYLAND.
YEP, THEY REALLY ARE MAKING
THEIR OWN DOGS...
OH, BABY, THOSE THINGS
ARE LOOKING MIGHTY FINE.
AND 50 OTHER KINDS OF SAUSAGE.
BRATS, GERMAN LINKS,
CHICKEN, BOCKWURST.
IT'S PURE SAUSAGE.
AND IT'S DELICIOUS?
IT'S VERY DELICIOUS.
MY MOUTH'S WATERING.
MMM.
NOBODY DOES IT BETTER.
AND A CAJUN.
BECAUSE THEY'VE BEEN AT IT
FOR 80 YEARS.
MY GRANDFATHER CAME OVER
FROM GERMANY,
BUILT THIS BUILDING
IN '37.
HERE WE GO.
NOW JERRY EICHENTOPF
IS RUNNING THE PLACE...
FILLING SAUSAGE
IS MY LOVE.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE TODAY?
WITH HIS WIFE GRETCHEN...
HERE YOU ARE.
AND THEIR THREE DAUGHTERS.
CHRISTIE, HEIDI
AND REBECCA--
THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM
FOR EVERYBODY HERE.
(Guy) WHAT IS YOUR FAVORITE
THING THAT YOU MAKE HERE?
HOT DOGS.
WOW.
MADE THE SAME WAY
JERRY'S GRANDFATHER
FIRST MADE 'EM BACK IN 1937.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OLD-FASHIONED WIENERS--HOT DOGS.
OKAY.
WE USE BULL MEAT,
LIKE A BIG BULL.
LIKE A--
NICE AND LEAN--
IT'S GOT GOOD SINEW.
SO THE THINGS WE TYPICALLY
DON'T LIKE ABOUT BULL MEAT--
THAT IT IS TOUGH,
AND THAT IT DOES HAVE SINEW.
EXACTLY THE REASON WHY
THEY MADE HOT DOGS OUT OF IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BONELESS PICNIC.
THE BOTTOM PART THAT HAS
THE BIGGER BONE IN IT,
MORE MUSCLE-Y--THAT'S THAT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF PORK CHEEKS.
PORK RIGHT HERE.
PORK RIGHT THERE.
AND WHY THAT?
IT JUST HAS
A GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT TO THAT.
THAT'S GOT
A LITTLE NITRATE
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR
IN THERE.
AND WHAT'S
THE NITRATE FOR?
SO IT DOESN'T SPOIL, AND IT
ALSO GIVES IT THAT RED COLOR.
OUT OF THAT ENTIRE CONTAINER,
HOW MUCH WAS THE NITRATE?
ABOUT 1/2 TEASPOON.
THAT MUCH IS NITRATE?
FOR ABOUT 100 POUNDS OF MEAT.
THAT'S NOT VERY MUCH.
OH, THAT'S THE BIGGEST BUFFALO
CHOPPER I'VE EVER SEEN.
THIS THING
WAS BOUGHT IN 1937.
THIS IS GONNA
SPIN LIKE THIS,
AND THIS BOWL'S GONNA TURN
AT THE SAME TIME.
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
THAT'S AWESOME.
NOW TO KEEP IT COLD,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE TO ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF ICE TO THAT.
BECAUSE IT STARTS
TO GUM UP, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
OKAY, WHAT'S
THE FIRST SEASONING?
WE'RE GONNA USE
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT
OF CORIANDER...
WOW.
CELERY SALT,
GROUND MUSTARD, PAPRIKA,
A LITTLE BIT
OF GROUND MACE.
MACE, HUH?
HOW LONG
DOES THIS USUALLY TAKE?
IT JUST TAKES ABOUT
FOUR OR FIVE MINUTES
TO GET HER DOWN
TO WHERE IT'S REAL NICE.
ARE WE GONNA ADD FAT?
A LITTLE PORK GEL--A LITTLE
SWEETER THAN YOUR BACK FAT.
SEE HOW IT'S HANGING TOGETHER?
WE'VE GOT GOOD BINDING.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
FROM THIS MACHINE,
AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT IN OUR STUFFER.
IN THE TURBO BATCH 9000?
IN THE TURBO BATCH 9000.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GRAB OURSELVES A CASING.
NATURAL SHEEP INTESTINES.
A LITTLE KNOT
ON THE END OF IT. DIG IT.
WHOA.
AND WE'RE MAKING SAUSAGES.
YES, WE ARE.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TRY IT?
OH, HEY,
YOU KNOW I DO.
GONNA TAKE MY BLING OFF
FOR THIS. WHOA!
CAN'T YOU JUST MAKE IT COME OUT
A LITTLE BIT SLOWER?
I DID.
OH.
YOU JUST SPIN
EVERY OTHER ONE OF 'EM.
♪ DA DA DA DA DUN ♪
SKIP ONE, SPIN ONE.
LOOK AT THOSE THINGS--
IT'S LIKE A HOT DOG LASSO
ON THE RANCH AT FLAVOR TOWN.
SO WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
ALL RIGHT, THEN WE'RE GONNA
HANG 'EM ON THOSE STICKS,
SPREAD 'EM OUT SO THEY CAN
GET SMOKE ALL THE WAY AROUND.
I AM DRIVING
THE HOT DOG TRUCK! HA HA!
INTO THE SMOKER.
OKAY. TWO HOURS?
HOW LONG?
TWO HOURS.
OH, DO YOU WANT ME
TO STAND HERE AND GUARD?
I'M WITH YA.
HOLY MOLY!
THAT IS SO AWESOME.
HOW LONG DOES IT GO
IN THE HOT WATER FOR?
15 MINUTES
JUST TO GET THE INTERNAL
TEMPERATURE TO 155.
MEAT CHIQUITA BANANAS.
AND THEN YOU PUT 'EM
IN THE COLD WATER.
TO CHILL 'EM OFF
REAL QUICK.
SO THIS IS DONE
AND READY TO ROCK?
DONE AND READY TO ROCK.
OKAY. OH.
GOT THE SNAP.
I MEAN, IT IS TENDER,
CREAMY, JUICY. OH.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
OH.
AND RIGHT TO THE GRILL.
JUST ENOUGH TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE MARK.
MMM.
STUDDED WITH FLAVOR.
THERE WE GO.
I'M DONE WITH THE BUN.
MMM.
I SAW EVERYTHING
THAT WENT IN THERE.
THAT'S AS REAL AS YOU CAN GET.
YOU THE MAN.
IT'S PERFECT.
THERE'S THE OLD-FASHIONED.
YOU CAN'T REALLY BEAT
A HOT DOG OFF THE GRILL.
OR WHATEVER
JERRY'S GOT GOING...
PERFECT SAUSAGE.
OUT FRONT
ON THE SIDEWALK GRILL,
A 22-YEAR TRADITION.
WE PUT IT OUT THERE.
IT WAS A BIG HIT.
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
YOU'VE GOT IT.
THEY ALWAYS
HAVE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
THIS IS ONE
OF MY BEST FRIENDS.
HE WAS MY ROOMMATE
IN COLLEGE, PETE HOWE,
AND HE LIVES UP HERE
IN PORTLAND.
IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
OUT OF THIS WORLD.
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?
A SMOKED PORK LINK.
SMOKED PORK.
DELICIOUS.
THIS IS A CHICKEN SAUSAGE.
I'VE HAD MANY OF THEM.
THEY KNOW WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
ALWAYS HAVE,
FROM THE SMOKER
TO THE GRILL...
HI, WHAT CAN I GET
FOR YOU?
TO THE DELI...
CAN I GET SOME
OF YOUR BOCKWURST?
WITH THOSE 50 KINDS OF SAUSAGE
AND ALL KINDS OF DELI MEAT
THE FAMILY'S BEEN CRANKING OUT
FOR 80 YEARS...
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
LIKE ROAST BEEF,
CORNED BEEF...
THERE YOU ARE.
AND FRESH SMOKED PASTRAMI.
DELICIOUS.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
WE'VE GOT BOTTOM ROUND TRIMMED
OF QUITE A BIT OF THE FAT.
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX IT IN THAT
SALT-NITRATE-SUGAR SOLUTION.
TAKE OUR PICKLING SPICE...
OKAY.
SOME MUSTARD SEED, PEPPERS.
SOME PEPPERCORNS--
YOU'VE GOT SOME HERBS
IN THERE, CORIANDER.
LEAVE THIS RUB ON THERE?
THREE WEEKS.
REALLY?
THE CURING PROCESS
IS DONE.
WE'LL JUST RINSE
HER OFF.
OVER HERE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR COARSE BLACK PEPPER.
YOU KIND OF PACK IT
IN THERE A LITTLE BIT.
LOOK LIKE
IT'S READY TO GO?
YEAH.
AND NOW WE'LL GO PUT THESE
IN THE SMOKER.
LEAVE IT IN THERE
FOR OVERNIGHT.
WOW.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA--
DO YOU HAVE TO TALK?
JUST LOOK AT IT
FOR A SECOND.
OPEN UP THE HOT TUB.
JUST LAY IT IN THERE.
FOR ABOUT
THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
IS THIS THE WAY
EVERYBODY DOES IT?
NO. ALL YOUR MODERN ONES NOW
STEAM IN THE SAME SMOKEHOUSE.
SO A LITTLE MORE
LABOR INTENSIVE,
BUT THIS IS WHAT'S BRINGING OUT
THE QUALITY PRODUCT.
THIS BRINGS OUT THE QUALITY.
LET'S SEE WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE.
WOW. LOOK AT THAT.
I'LL LET IT COOL
A LITTLE BIT.
I'LL HOLD IT.
I THINK
HE'S RUNNING OFF WITH IT.
SO YOU'RE HANDING
THE MEAT AND ME OFF.
HANDING YOU OFF.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A PASTRAMI SANDWICH FOR YA.
DO YOU LIKE PASTRAMI?
UH-HUH.
YOU LIKE
A LOT OF PASTRAMI?
UH-HUH.
THIS IS
MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH GOOD.
THERE YOU ARE.
READY?
MMM.
MMM. THAT IS AWESOME.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S SLICED SO THIN,
THERE'S ONLY ONE SIDE. MMM.
THAT'S KILLER PASTRAMI--
ALL THRILLER, NO FILLER.
(man) THE FOOD IS GOOD.
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
THIS IS JUST PERFECT.
(Jerry)
SAUSAGE, BABY, SAUSAGE.
DO YOU EVER MAIL
TO SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA,
TO PEOPLE THAT
HAVE DONE SHOWS HERE?
(Heidi) I GUESS
WE WILL NOW.
I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW
WHERE THAT CAME FROM.
UP NEXT...
THEY CALL IT
A KIND OF LASAGNA.
I'M HEADIN' HOME TO NOR-CAL.
ONE OF A KIND.
TO CHECK OUT
A PUERTO RICAN PLACE...
(speaking Spanish)
MY SISTER FELL IN LOVE WITH.
IT'S FUN.
IT'S A NICE ATMOSPHERE.
MMM. THAT'S WAY UP THERE IN SOME
OF THE BEST THINGS I'VE HAD.
ONE OF THE GREAT THINGS
ABOUT TRIPLE "D"
IS ALL THE RECOMMENDATIONS
OF JOINTS I GOTTA CHECK OUT.
SO HERE I AM
IN MY BACKYARD OF NOR-CAL.
AND NO, THE RECOMMENDATION
DIDN'T COME
FROM AN E-MAIL THIS TIME.
ONCE IN A WHILE, A GUY'S GOTTA
LISTEN TO HIS LITTLE SISTER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE BOMB?
IT'S THE BOMB.
REALLY THE BOMB?
IT IS.
IT TOOK YOU TWO YEARS TO GET
HERE. JUST WAIT. YOU'LL SEE.
OW.
THE POLLO AL HORNO.
THE POLLO.
NO JOKE.
MY SISTER MORGAN'S BEEN ALL
OVER ME TO CHECK OUT THIS JOINT
FOR SOME REAL-DEAL
PUERTO RICAN COOKING.
AND IT'S FREE-RANGE CHICKEN.
THE MEAT'S GRASS-FED.
AND IT'S FUN.
IT'S A NICE ATMOSPHERE.
AND IT AIN'T JUST HER...
THE FOOD IS JUST DELICIOUS.
I WOULDN'T THINK TO FIND
A PUERTO RICAN RESTAURANT
IN SAN RAFAEL.
ONE OF A KIND.
THIS IS AUTHENTIC.
UNO CUBANO.
THANKS TO SOL HERNANDEZ,
WHOSE DAD WAS BORN
IN PUERTO RICO,
AND THEN DISCOVERED
THE ISLAND FOR HERSELF...
CAMARONES CRIOLLOS.
WHEN SHE SPENT 9 MONTHS THERE
AT THE AGE OF 20.
I REALLY WANTED TO BRING
MY PASSION FOR THAT SIDE OF ME
HERE AND SHARE IT
WITH PEOPLE.
SO NOW SHE'S BRINGING
PUERTO RICAN CLASSICS...
(speaking Spanish)
TO NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
HABICHUELA ROSADA,
WHICH IS PINK BEANS, RICE.
PLANTAINS.
ONE GARLIC, ONE SWEET.
AND TOSTONES--
I LOVE TOSTONES.
AND THIS ONE.
THE PASTELóN DE CARNE--
THEY CALL IT A KIND OF LASAGNA.
IT'S BECOME ONE
OF SOL'S OWN FAVORITES.
WE'RE MAKING PICADILLO.
OKAY.
THIS IS GONNA GO
IN OUR PASTELóN.
THE PUERTO RICAN LASAGNA.
YES.
(beatboxing)
PICA--PICA--PICADILLO.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH SOME VEGETABLE OIL--
LET THAT GET
A LITTLE BIT HOT--
A LOT OF BEEF.
YOU WANT TO GET IT
COOKED ABOUT HALFWAY...
OKAY.
BECAUSE THEN YOU WANT
TO COOK THE REST OF THE WAY
WITH ALL THE SEASONINGS
AND STUFF.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE COOKED
TWO THIRDS OF THE WAY.
EXACTLY.
START WITH ADOBO SEASONING
RIGHT HERE.
THEN ADOBO SEASONING TAKES
A PRETTY PREVALENT ROLE--
TURMERIC, ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER, SALT, PEPPER.
RIGHT.
SO NOW--
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SOFRITO.
THE GREEN BELL PEPPERS
AND THE JALAPEÑOS
AND THE ONIONS
AND THE GARLIC AND THE CILANTRO
ALL GO TOGETHER.
YEAH.
I CAN SMELL THAT
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
JUST REGULAR TOMATO SAUCE.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE MEXICAN OREGANO.
SO NOW THE OLIVES
GO DOWN.
YEP.
SO YOU GET SOME OF THAT
BRINY FLAVOR FROM THE OLIVES.
MM-HMM.
20 MINUTES OF SIMMERING.
IT'S LIKE PUERTO RICAN
SLOPPY JOE.
EXACTLY.
SO WHERE'S THE REST
OF THE BAT?
WE'RE JUST GONNA USE THIS TO
MASH UP OUR SWEET PLANTAINS.
IS THIS GONNA BE LIKE
THE NOODLE FOR THE LASAGNA?
EXACTLY.
NO PASTA INVOLVED.
BUT I LIKE TO CALL IT
PUERTO RICAN LASAGNA.
THAT'S WHAT MY SISTER
TOLD ME.
YEAH.
OKAY, SO THIS ALL GETS
SMEARED DOWN AT THE BOTTOM.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IN OUR
GROUND BEEF STRAIGHT ONTO HERE.
MAKE SURE YOU GET SOME
OF THE JUICE IN THERE.
MAKE SURE I DROOL
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
NOT EVERYONE USES OLIVES.
THE PLANTAINS
ARE ACTUALLY SO SWEET...
MMM.
THAT YOU NEED TO HAVE
SOMETHING TO OFFSET IT.
I MEAN--
BALANCE IT OUT.
PUERTO RICAN FOOD--
I THINK PEOPLE
ALSO GET A MISUNDERSTANDING--
IS NOT REALLY SUPER SPICY.
NOT SPICY, NO.
HUEVOS--I'M GONNA DO SIX,
BECAUSE I WANT TO MAKE SURE--
LIVING ON THE EDGE,
RIGHT?
I'M GONNA BEAT THOSE UP.
THIS IS JUST GONNA GO OVER THIS.
SO THAT'LL SEEP
IN THERE A LITTLE BIT...
EXACTLY.
AND HELP BIND
THIS TOGETHER.
EXACTLY.
OKAY.
TRADITIONALLY, PEOPLE
WOULD PUT GREEN BEANS ON THIS.
MMM.
WE'RE GONNA USE CHEESE,
BECAUSE IT'S WHAT
WE LIKE TO DO HERE.
THIS LOOKS LIKE SOME
DYNAMITE JACK. WHO'S IT FROM?
YES. THIS IS FROM
MARIN CHEESE COMPANY.
MMM.
YOU SHOULD SERVE THAT
BY ITSELF.
THIS IS THE BEST.
AND THESE
ARE THE RED BELL PEPPERS,
AND YOU CAN GET
FANCIER WITH THESE
IF YOU WANT TO DO
LIKE A CRISSCROSS
OR WRITE "I LOVE YOU"
FOR VALENTINE'S DAY.
OH, THANKS.
I DIDN'T
GET YOU ANYTHING.
ISN'T THAT SWEET?
I KNOW.
SO WE WRAP IT UP.
I SEAL IT WITH PLASTIC
AND THEN ALUMINUM FOIL.
SO YOU KEEP ALL THE MOISTURE IN.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
YES.
THIS IS GONNA COOK
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
OKAY.
SO HERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, WOW, YOU GET
THE SALTINESS OF THE MEAT,
AND YOU GET SOME OF THAT BRINE
FROM THE OLIVE.
THE PLANTAINS ON THE BOTTOM
IS WHAT MAKES IT, THOUGH.
YEAH.
IT BRINGS IT
ALL TOGETHER.
WHERE'S THE HOT SAUCE?
YOU DON'T BUY IT THIS WAY.
YOU BOTTLE IT YOURSELF.
WE MAKE THIS.
SO WHAT'S IN HERE?
VINEGAR BASE WITH AN ASSORTMENT
OF DIFFERENT CHILIES.
MMM. THAT'S WAY UP THERE IN SOME
OF THE BEST THINGS I'VE HAD.
AWESOME.
THE GREEN OLIVES THAT
JUST ADD A LITTLE SALTINESS...
AND A LITTLE SPICE
FROM THE HOT SAUCE.
I'M IMPRESSED.
I MEAN, THERE'S A LINE
OUT THE DOOR.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
WELL, IT'S ALL FAMILY-STYLE.
EVERYBODY SITS.
IF SOMEBODY WALKS IN
AND SEES AN OPEN SEAT,
THEY'LL SIT WITH YOU.
THIS IS HOW IT IS
EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
ALWAYS CRAZY IN HERE.
(woman) AND THE WAY THAT
THEY'VE PAINTED EVERYTHING
MAKES ME FEEL MORE LIKE
I'M IN A DIFFERENT CULTURE.
SOMETIMES IT TELL THEM
IT'S THE CHEAPEST VACATION
YOU'RE EVER GONNA TAKE.
JUST AS GOOD AS THE FOOD THAT
I HAD WHEN I WAS IN PUERTO RICO.
FROM THE MASHED PLANTAINS
AND GARLIC TOPPED WITH SHRIMP
CALLED MOFONGO...
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
WELL, YOU OUT THE FUN-O
IN THE MOFONGO.
TO ALL KINDS
OF FRESH SANDWICHES...
SANDWICH DE HUEVO.
I LOVE THE SANDWICHES.
THEIR CUBANO SANDWICH.
VEGGIE DELUXE--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
PERFECTLY COOKED.
IT'S JUST SO GOOD.
AND THE TOP SELLER
IN THE WHOLE JOINT...
BISTEC SANDWICH--
DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
SANDWICH BISTEC.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE PUTTING
SOME LIGHT OLIVE OIL,
A HANDFUL OF ONIONS.
YOU GOTTA SAUTé THESE
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
AND THIS IS TOP-QUALITY
GRASS-FED SIRLOIN.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR SEASONING.
AND THIS
IS ADOBO SEASONING.
EXACTLY.
NOW I HAVE A PhD
IN STEAK SANDWICH--
A PRETTY HEAVY DIET.
SO THE TOP SIRLOIN
SLICED REALLY THIN--
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICES.
YEAH, IT'S A TON OF JUICE
AND NOT TOO MUCH FAT.
WHILE THAT'S COOKING,
WE CAN GET OUR BREAD READY.
WE'RE JUST USING FRESH
LOCALLY BAKED FRENCH BREAD.
SWISS CHEESE.
THIS IS GONNA GO RIGHT ON HERE.
THE ONIONS GO ON.
YEP.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IT ON
OUR SANDWICH PRESS OVER HERE.
HOW LONG?
PROBABLY LIKE TWO MINUTES,
THREE MINUTES.
I SEE YOU. OKAY.
IT'S READY TO GO. TAKE IT OFF.
I'M GONNA OPEN IT UP.
WE'VE GOT OUR AVOCADO.
THIS IS OUR
GARLIC MAYONNAISE.
STICK THAT ON THERE.
DON'T BE SHY.
LOOK AT THAT--
AVOCADO, GRILLED ONIONS.
MMM.
MEAT'S NICE AND TENDER.
THAT'S LIKE PUERTO RICAN,
CUBAN PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
WHAT'S IT CALLED AGAIN?
SANDWICH BISTEC.
BISTEC?
BISTEC, YEAH.
IT'S NO "ME-STEAK."
IT'S JUST REALLY GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE ELSE
TO GET ANYTHING THIS GOOD.
THIS IS MY SON HUNTER.
YOU'VE HAD A LOT OF MY FOOD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THIS?
IT'S PRETTY OUTSTANDING.
PRETTY OUTSTANDING.
IT'S A WONDERFUL PLACE.
THANKS FOR INVITING ME.
GREAT IDEA.
THANKS FOR COMING.
SEE, I EVEN LISTEN
TO MY LITTLE SISTER.
NEXT STOP...
PICK UP STEAMERS.
WESTPORT, CONNECTICUT...
JUST A FUN PLACE TO COME.
TO A DIVE BAR ON A BARGE...
PUT IT IN THE BROTH,
IN THE BUTTER,
DOWN THE HATCH.
FOR BUCKETS OF CLAMS.
MMM. OH.
SO I'M HERE
IN WESTPORT, CONNECTICUT.
NOW MY AUNT GERRY AND UNCLE PETE
USED TO LIVE CLOSE BY,
AND I REMEMBER, AS A KID,
RIDING MY BIKE DOWN HERE
LOOKING FOR A PIZZA PLACE.
WELL, THINGS DON'T
REALLY CHANGE, DO THEY?
'CAUSE 30 YEARS LATER,
I'M BACK IN TOWN DOING WHAT?
LOOKING FOR SOME FOOD
HERE AT THE BLACK DUCK CAFE
UNDER THE I-95 BRIDGE
ON A BARGE.
NOW FOLKS AROUND HERE SAY
IT'S A FUNKY JOINT
YOU JUST GOTTA CHECK OUT.
IT'S A DIVE.
IT'S THE DUCK.
THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE IT.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
WE'LL PUT IT ON YOUR TAB.
YOU CAN HAVE A BURGER,
HAVE A BEER AND JUST RELAX.
JUST A FUN PLACE TO COME,
AND THE FOOD IS ALWAYS GOOD.
HAS BEEN SINCE PETER AITKIN
BOUGHT THE JOINT
MORE THAN 30 YEARS AGO.
HOW'S EVERYTHING GOING HERE?
IT WAS A RESTAURANT
BEFORE I BOUGHT IT.
I TURNED IT INTO A BAR.
WINGS.
AND I'VE ALWAYS THOUGHT
WE'RE PROBABLY A BAR
THAT SERVES FOOD.
RUEBEN, SMALL BACON CHEESE--
PICK IT UP.
BUT THIS BAR FOOD'S
BEING DONE
BY CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF
TIM MILLER.
I LOVE IT. IT'S MY FAVORITE
RESTAURANT TO COME TO.
BACON CHEESEBURGER.
AND HE'S SERIOUS
ABOUT DOING THINGS RIGHT.
TWO BURGERS, THREE KIDS' DOGS--
PICK 'EM UP.
FROM BAR BASICS...
IF YOU WANT A BURGER,
YOU COME TO THE DUCK.
TO A WHOLE LOT MORE...
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS HAVING?
THE STEAK IS REALLY GOOD.
REAL SEAFOOD,
AND YOU CAN TASTE IT.
THE LOBSTER ROLLS--
BUTTERY FRESH, SWEET.
PICK UP STEAMERS.
(bell dings)
A COUPLE BEERS, SOME CLAMS--
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
THE BIG FAVORITE HERE?
YEAH, I SELL
A TON OF STEAMERS.
I'M GONNA WASH 'EM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I GOT CORNMEAL HERE.
YOU'RE PUTTING
THE CORNMEAL IN IT,
BECAUSE THIS IS GONNA
HELP CLEAN OUT THE SYSTEM,
SO YOU DON'T GET A BUNCH OF SAND
WHEN YOU BITE INTO THE STEAMERS.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S A BIG STEAMER.
WOW.
OKAY, SO EVERYBODY'S
HAVING A LITTLE BIT
OF A CORNMEAL PARTY--
I OFTEN DO THIS FOR MY BUNIONS.
STIR 'EM AROUND.
GENERALLY LET 'EM SOAK FOR
AN HOUR AND A HALF, TWO HOURS.
WATER FOR THE STEAMERS.
NOW YOU ADD TO THE STEAMERS
A LITTLE ITALIAN SEASONING,
WHICH IS OREGANO, PARSLEY,
ROSEMARY, A LITTLE THYME.
IT ALWAYS TAKES
A LITTLE THYME, DOESN'T IT?
A LITTLE THYME,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE PARMESAN CHEESE...
PARMESAN CHEESE NOW?
YEAH.
REALLY?
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
SOMETHING NEW FOR ME.
A LITTLE SONOMA COUNTY
WHITE WINE...
THIS IS CLARIFIED BUTTER.
VERY NICE.
MAKE A NICE
LITTLE BROTH GOING HERE.
FIVE MINUTES?
IT'S GONNA TAKE A GOOD
FIVE MINUTES, PROBABLY, YEAH.
(whistles)
THERE'S GONNA BE
EXTRA BROTH SO...
YES, THERE IS.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
WHAT, DID THE WESTPORT HIGH
FOOTBALL TEAM SHOW UP?
WHO'S GONNA EAT ALL THAT?
THAT'S OUR PORTION.
A LITTLE DRAWN BUTTER,
GARNISH, A LITTLE LEMON WEDGE,
AND THAT'S IT.
MMM.
OH.
YOU REALLY GET
TO TASTE THE CLAM FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT OVERDONE WITH A BUNCH
OF BLAH BLAH BLAH BLAH BLAH.
RIGHT.
AND I LIKE A LOT OF BLAH
BLAH BLAH BLAH BLAH.
YEAH.
MAYBE YOU'VE SEEN THE SHOW.
A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON. MMM.
I GOTTA GET BUSY
ON THAT.
CAN I GET SOME GARLIC BREAD,
MAYBE A COLD ONE?
I COULD JUST
DRINK THE BROTH.
THAT'S SOUP.
OH, THAT'S AWESOME.
WHAT?
THEY'RE VERY GOOD.
PUT IT IN THE BROTH,
IN THE BUTTER, DOWN THE HATCH.
THE CLAMS HE HAS HERE
ARE JUST TO DIE FOR.
AND HE'S CRANKING OUT
75,000 A YEAR--
THE STEAMERS...
LARGE BELLY, PLEASE.
DEEP-FRIED...
SWEET, TENDER.
BAKED...
STUFFED CLAMS.
THE STUFFED CLAMS
ARE AWESOME.
AND THIS CLASSIC...
AN ORDER OF CLAMS CASINO.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE DRAWN BUTTER
AND THEN THE WHITE WINE...
OKAY.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
A LITTLE ITALIAN SEASONING.
BACON PIECES
AND A LITTLE PARMESAN ON TOP.
INTO THE BROILER.
FIVE MINUTES?
NOT EVEN.
ARE THEY DONE?
HOT JUICE.
YEAH. THEY'RE DONE.
A LITTLE GARNISH.
I WISH YOU WOULD HAVE
MADE YOURSELF SOME.
(laughs)
MMM.
THAT'S JUST SIMPLE GOODNESS
RIGHT THERE.
GOOD STUFF?
THAT IS AWESOME.
MMM.
MY AUNT GERRY AND UNCLE PETE,
I THINK IF THEY WOULD HAVE
COME AND HAD THESE,
THEY MIGHT NOT HAVE MOVED.
THESE ARE AWESOME. UH-HUH.
I'M GONNA EAT ALL OF 'EM.
IT'S FABULOUS. THE BACON'S
CRISP. THEY TASTE DELICIOUS.
SOME CLAMS WITH SOME WHITE WINE
AND SOME GARLIC,
I MEAN--
YOU CAN'T GET BETTER
THAN THAT.
ANYTHING YOU PUT BACON ON
YOU CAN'T LOSE.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD HERE.
NACHOS.
WE ORDERED THE SUPREME NACHOS
AND THE CHICKEN WINGS,
AND THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
THAT'S A BIG SERVING
OF MOZZARELLA.
OH, YEAH. FANTASTIC.
BUT THE REAL HEAVY HITTER...
THOSE FOUR BURGERS,
I COULD TAKE 'EM.
IS THE BURGER.
MEAT STUFFED
WITH CHEESE--AWESOME.
YOU STUFF THE BURGER?
RIGHT.
JUICY, TONS OF FLAVOR.
THE CHEESE JUST OOZING.
WITH BLUE, CHEDDAR
OR CHECK OUT THIS ONE.
DO YOU STUFF BRIE CHEESE
IN A BURGER?
YES.
OH.
WE'RE DOING THAT FOR SURE.
WE'RE DOING THAT ONE TODAY.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
SPLIT IT APART.
THAT'S A BIG BURGER.
YEAH, IT IS--
12 OUNCES.
WE'VE GOT SMALL--
8-OUNCE.
YEAH.
WE ADD THE BRIE. WE JUST TRY
TO USE LIKE 2 OR 3 OUNCES.
TRYING TO PUT
A LITTLE EXTRA IN,
BECAUSE IF SOMEBODY
ORDERS IT MEDIUM WELL OR WELL,
SOME OF THE CHEESE
OOZES OUT.
(whistles) I DIG IT.
AND THIS
IS THE TRICKY PART.
YOU GOTTA MAKE SURE
YOU FORM IT
SO WE MAKE SURE
THAT CHEESE STAYS IN.
THEN SEASON IT WITH SALT
AND PEPPER. READY FOR THE GRILL.
AND YOU DON'T THINK THAT'S
GONNA LEAK OUT OF THERE?
IT SHOULDN'T.
AND WHAT DO WE
SERVE THIS WITH?
LETTUCE, TOMATO, ONION.
COLESLAW, PICKLES.
(whistles) OH, YOU'RE IN LUCK
AT THE BLACK DUCK.
PRETTY BIG HOT.
YEAH.
PRETTY BIG HOT?
MMM.
THE BRIE IS ON POINT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THAT'S THE ONE
TO GO FOR RIGHT THERE.
I EXPECT A BUFFALO WING,
MAYBE SOME STEAMERS,
OF COURSE, A BURGER,
BUT THE FACT
THAT YOU GUYS TAKE THE TIME
TO STUFF IT
WITH BRIE, DIFFERENT CHEESES,
GOOD COOKING OUT, MAN.
THE STUFFED BURGER'S
OUR FAVORITE.
THE BEST BURGERS
IN TOWN.
YOU CAN'T GET
A BAD MEAL HERE.
IF IT'S NOT SEAFOOD,
IT'S THE BURGERS.
OR MAYBE SOMETHING YOU WOULDN'T
EXPECT ON A BEACHED BARGE...
STEAK AU POIVRE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHAT A NICE SURPRISE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
STUFFED CLAMS.
THE BLACK DUCK CAFE...
PICK IT UP.
ON A BARGE UNDER I-95...
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
IS A LOCAL FAVORITE
IN WESTPORT, CONNECTICUT...
THE PLACE
THAT EVERYBODY COMES.
SERVED WITH
THE SPEED OF LIGHT.
THANKS, PETE.
WHERE OWNER PETER AITKIN...
STEAMERS.
AND CHEF TIM MILLER
ARE DOING DIVE BAR THEIR WAY...
LOBSTER ROLL--PICK IT UP.
FROM FRESH ATLANTIC STEAMERS
TO BURGERS STUFFED WITH BRIE...
JUICY--I LOVE IT.
AND SERIOUS SPECIALS
LIKE STEAK AU POIVRE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE STEAK?
REALLY GOOD FLAVORING.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
STEAK AU POIVRE.
WOW.
16-OUNCE NEW YORK.
I'M GONNA TENDERIZE IT
A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE NOT GONNA
BEAT IT UP.
WHERE'S MY MONEY?
WHERE'S--I'M SORRY,
THAT'S A DIFFERENT SHOW.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT
WITH A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL IN THE PAN.
SO WE'RE JUST AT THE SMOKE
POINT. NOW IT GOES DOWN?
RIGHT.
IT'S GETTING HOT
IN HERE, NELLY. OKAY.
IT'S BASICALLY STEWING.
IT'S SPITTING.
NOW YOU DON'T GRILL IT
AND MAKE YOUR SAUCE IN THE PAN.
YOU DO IT ALL
IN THE PAN.
YEAH, A 1-PAN DEAL.
AH, NICE LITTLE CRUST
ON THAT, HUH?
YEAH.
I'M GONNA LEAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT IN THERE.
WE GOT THE SHALLOTS. GARLIC--
I DON'T WANT TO BURN IT.
GREEN PEPPERCORNS--
DO YOU LIKE THE GREEN PEPPERS?
OH, BRING IT, BABY.
WHY DON'T WE JUST GRAB
THE WHOLE THING?
OH, OKAY.
I'LL GONNA THROW SOME BRANDY
IN THERE.
I'LL BE OVER HERE. OH.
AND TO THINK THAT I FORGOT
THE MARSHMALLOW STICKS.
I THINK WE SHOULD DEFINITELY
TAKE ANOTHER HIT
OR POUR SOME IN THE PAN.
COME HERE TO
TIM'S EYEBROW REMOVAL PROGRAM.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE DEMI-GLACE,
FINISH IT
WITH A LITTLE CREAM.
THAT'S GONNA SIMMER
FOR A MINUTE OR TWO.
I'M GONNA SERVE IT
WITH ASPARAGUS TONIGHT.
NOW YOU PRE-BLANCH THOSE?
YES.
YOU JUST HAVE
TO BRING 'EM UP TO TEMP?
RIGHT.
THAT'S AWESOME.
WOW.
WE LOADED UP
ON THE, UH...
PEPPERCORN.
PEPPERCORN THERE, HUH?
MMM. LOOK AT THAT.
I CAN'T REALLY TELL YOU
THAT I WAS EXPECTING TO SEE
A STEAK AU POIVRE
USING THE FRESH PEPPERCORNS.
MMM.
WHAT A NICE SURPRISE.
ASPARAGUS ARE PERFECT.
IT'S AN OLD BARGE
NEXT TO THE WATER.
I'LL GIVE YOU
THE SEAFOOD PIECES.
BUT THIS--THAT'S A NICE MOVE.
THANKS, CHEF.
THANKS, BRO.
THE FLAVOR'S FANTASTIC,
AND IT'S A GREAT CUT.
IT'S A GREAT LOCAL HANGOUT.
EVERYBODY
KIND OF KNOWS EVERYBODY.
THIS PLACE IS THE BEST.
IT'S GOT GREAT FOOD.
BUFFALO SHRIMP.
IT'S THE DUCK.
NEVER A DULL MOMENT
AROUND HERE.
IT'S AN ORIGINAL.
YOU WILL NOT FIND A PLACE
LIKE THIS ON THE PLANET.
IT'S AWESOME.
I'VE BEEN HERE 30 YEARS,
AND GOD WILLING,
I'LL DO IT
ANOTHER 10 OR 20.
GOOD STUFF.
THANKS A LOT.
THANKS FOR COMING DOWN.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
(cheers and applause)
THEY APPLAUD YOU.
I TOLD EVERYBODY IF THEY
CLAPPED, FREE DRINKS,
SO THAT'S KIND OF
WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I CAN DEAL WITH THAT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT WE GOT PLENTY
MORE JOINTS TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON TRIPLE "D."
YOU GOTTA
WATCH THAT CORNER.
OH!
(laughs)