HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
CAME IN EXPECTING
BAR FOOD.
DIVES WORTH A DRIVE...
SALMON B.L.T.
HALFWAY BETWEEN MILWAUKEE
AND CHICAGO...
HOW WE DOIN', RAY?
AN 80-YEAR-OLD JOINT...
ALL THE FOOD HERE
IS DELICIOUS.
WHERE THEY'RE SPIKIN'
THE SEAFOOD...
WHISKEY SHRIMP DINNER.
GOD, THE SHRIMP
IS KILLER.
AND EVEN THE OLIVE OIL'S
HOMEMADE.
BRING YOUR OWN OLIVE OIL
FROM YOUR OWN RANCH IN GREECE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IN CLEVELAND...
SEARED TUNA
WITH CARIBBEAN FRIES.
AN OLD NIGHTCLUB
FROM BACK IN THE '30s...
IT'S A NICE BAR
WITH REALLY GOOD FOOD.
ENJOY.
WITH THEY'RE FRESH SMOKIN'
SALMON FOR THEIR B.L.T.s...
THIS IS EXCELLENT.
ON A RIG OUT BACK.
(man) OKAY, BROTHER.
I'LL GET THE LID.
THANK YOU.
AND NEAR BUFFALO, NEW YORK...
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
A 19th-CENTURY
HUNTING LODGE...
COMIN' OUT
UP ON A CHEDDAR BURGER.
WHERE THEY'RE BIG
ON BURGERS...
HUGE--IT'S LIKE
A SIRLOIN ON A BUN.
EVEN IN A BOWL.
CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
MMM. THIS IS, NO KIDDING,
LIQUID CHEESEBURGER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON ROUTE 41, RIGHT BETWEEN
MILWAUKEE AND CHICAGO,
IS A LITTLE JOINT THAT--
WELL, MAYBE WE WOULDN'T
CALL IT A JOINT.
CALL IT A DIVE--EH,
I WOULDN'T CALL IT A DIVE.
LET'S JUST CALL IT
A SHANTY, ALL RIGHT?
IT'S ONE OF THOSE EXAMPLES
OF "DON'T JUDGE A BOOK
BY ITS COVER,"
'CAUSE WHAT'S GOIN' ON INSIDE
IS A GREEK FAMILY
KEEPIN' A TRADITION ALIVE.
WELCOME TO THE SHANTY.
OKAY, RANDY,
HOW'S IT GOIN'?
IT'S QUAINT,
VERY MUCH A SHANTY,
BUT WE LOVE IT.
WE GOT A CRAB CAKE DINNER
WITH EXTRA VEGGIES.
FOOD'S GREAT.
HELLO,
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
THE PEOPLE ARE GREAT.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
YOU JUST FEEL AT HOME.
THE WAY DIMITRI KALLIANIS FELT
WHEN HE FIRST WALKED IN HERE
THREE YEARS AGO.
ORDER UP.
SO HE AND HIS DAD DINO...
EVERYTHING IS GOOD?
BOUGHT THE 80-YEAR-OLD JOINT.
I GREW UP
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
WITH MY DAD.
RIGHT ON.
NOW THE TWO OF THEM ARE MAKIN'
THEIR MARK ON THE SHANTY.
AS FAR AS THE BUILDING
IS CONCERNED,
IT HASN'T CHANGED AT ALL.
BUT THE MENU'S
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
MUSSELS, EXTRA ORANGES.
EVERYTHING ON THAT MENU THAT'S
NEW, THE CUSTOMERS HAVE PICKED.
YOU BUILT A WHOLE MENU OFF OF
WHAT YOUR CUSTOMERS WANTED.
YEAH.
ALLIGATOR TAIL,
TABLE 14.
THE FOOD KEPT GOIN'
LIKE THIS,
AND NOW IT'S
ON THAT A-PLUS LEVEL.
THEY'VE ADDED
A LOT OF SEAFOOD.
FROM CRAB CAKES TO WALLEYE
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
WHISKEY SHRIMP DINNER.
WHISKEY SHRIMP.
IT IS, UH,
OUR SIGNATURE DISH HERE,
MOST POPULAR ITEM.
THAT SAUCE IS SO CREAMY AND JUST
SMOOTH. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE MAKIN' TARRAGON SAUCE
FOR WHISKEY SHRIMP.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH SOME SWEET CREAM BUTTER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA LET THAT MELT.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU GONNA ADD IN?
MINCED ONION,
FRESH MINCED GARLIC,
STIR THAT UP,
WHOLE LEMON SQUEEZED,
TWO PITCHERS
OF HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM...
IN CASE EVERYBODY AT HOME
MEASURES BY PITCHER.
THREE SQUIRTS
OF YELLOW MUSTARD...
PITCHERS AND SQUIRTS.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
FRESH TARRAGON LEAVES.
(whistles) AND LET THIS
REDUCE FOR HOW LONG?
UH, ABOUT A HALF
AN HOUR.
LET EVERYTHING
SOAK INTO EACH OTHER.
SO WE GOT OUR SAUCE MADE.
AND WE'RE MAKIN'
THE WHISKEY SHRIMP.
ALL RIGHT.
START OFF WITH A COUPLE SLICES
OF BUTTER.
YOU HAVE INTERESTING TERMINOLOGY
FOR THINGS--
PITCHER, SQUIRT, AND SLICES.
HEY, IT'S ALL--AS LONG
AS IT TASTES GOOD, RIGHT?
DE-TAIL THE SHRIMP.
THIS IS, UH, JUMBO WHITE
GULF SHRIMP FROM TEXAS.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT, PEPPER, GARLIC
AND OREGANO.
LET THIS SAUTé
TO ABOUT ALMOST DONE,
MAYBE 80% DONE.
SO WHILE THAT'S WORKIN'...
CHOP SOME FRESH FRENCH BREAD,
A LITTLE BIT OF, UH, OLIVE OIL.
WE'LL TOAST THAT UP.
NOW--THIS IS THE FUN PART--
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME JACK DANIEL'S WHISKEY.
THIS IS GONNA FLARE UP
PRETTY GOOD.
I LIKE TO CALL THIS, UH,
"GREEK LIGHTNING."
ADD OUR COOLED TARRAGON SAUCE,
ADD OUR TOAST POINTS,
PULL OUR SHRIMP OUT
AND WE'RE READY.
OOH.
WHISKEY SAUCE, FRESH TARRAGON
AND THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S SOME SAUCE. MMM.
GOD, THE SHRIMP ARE KILLER.
THERE'S NOTHIN' THAT, UH,
SHRIMP LIKE BETTER THAN GARLIC
AND BUTTER AND SOME TARRAGON.
OOH. I'LL TELL YOU, THE SHRIMP
IS DYNAMITE SHRIMP.
USIN' A GOOD-QUALITY PRODUCT
LIKE THAT--
I MEAN, THAT'S GREAT TEXTURE.
MMM. GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
GLAD YOU LIKED IT.
SAUCE IS GOOD.
IT'S GOOD SHRIMP.
I LIKE THE, UH, SAUCE
ON THE BREAD.
IT GETS ALL SOAKED IN, AND THEN
YOU GOT THE BREAD TO EAT.
IT'S JUST A TEN.
DOES IT USUALLY GET VEGETABLES,
TOO, IF THEY WANT?
YEP,
SAUTéED VEGETABLES.
THE WAY HE DOES HIS VEGETABLES,
THE FLAVOR IS JUST EXPLOSIVE.
(Dimitri)
VEGGIES ARE GOOD.
THE VEGETABLES ARE--
ARE FRESH,
AND THE OLIVE OIL ACTUALLY
COMES FROM THEIR FARM.
YOU GUYS BRING
YOUR OWN OLIVE OIL
FROM YOUR OWN
OLIVE OIL RANCH...
SURE.
IN GREECE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I MEAN, DON'T YOU THINK THAT'S
OVERDOING IT A LITTLE BIT?
NO.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
ALL THE FOOD HERE
IS DELICIOUS.
AND FOR EVERYTHING
THEY'VE ADDED TO THE MENU...
MUSHROOM AND SWISS BURGER.
THEY HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN
WHAT MADE THE SHANTY FAMOUS.
PORTERHOUSE, MEDIUM.
SHANTY STEAK HERE--
IT'S AWESOME.
BUT THEY'RE STILL ADDIN'
THEIR OWN TWIST.
CONCH FILET.
YOU HEARD HER--
A BACON-WRAPPED FILET
WITH...
FRESH CONCH.
AND CONCH. C-O-N-C-H?
YES.
SEASHELL--YOU HEAR
THE OCEAN IN IT.
RIGHT.
AND THAT'S BIG HERE
IN THE MILWAUKEE-CHICAGO AREA?
IT'S KIND OF LIKE A LITTLE
FUSION-SEAFOOD-STEAK...
IT'S YOUR VERSION
OF SURF AND TURF.
YES.
WE'RE USING FRESHLY TRIMMED,
TOP 6% OF CHOICE FILET MIGNON.
10-OUNCE FILET
TODAY...
WHOA.
NICE AND THICK.
WE'RE GONNA WRAP IT
IN BACON.
THROW A LITTLE PICK IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME CAJUN SPICE--
SEASONING SALT, CAYENNE PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
WHITE PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER, PAPRIKA
AND, UH, GREEK OREGANO
THAT MY DAD BRINGS OVER.
THAT MUST BE ONE FULL SUITCASE
WHEN THAT GUY COMES FROM GREECE.
IT IS.
OKAY, SO THIS IS
ALL READY TO GO?
YES, IT IS.
NOW ARE WE GONNA GRILL THIS?
WE GONNA PAN-SAUTé THIS?
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON A CHAR BROILER.
CHAR BROILER, OKAY.
YEP.
SO WE ARE GONNA GRILL IT.
THAT'S THE HOT SPOT?
THAT IS THE HOT SPOT.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA
SLICE, UM, FRESHLY BOILED CONCH.
WHAT DO YOU BOIL IT IN?
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
BUTTERMILK
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
ALL RIGHT.
SO NOW THIS GOES
TO A SAUTé PAN
WITH THE VEGGIES,
AND WE START COOKIN' THE SAUCE?
YEP.
START OFF
WITH SOME OLIVE OIL.
AND THAT'S
THE OLIVE OIL
THAT COMES
FROM YOUR DAD'S RANCH IN...
IN SPARTA, GREECE.
THIS ONE IS TWO WEEKS.
TWO WEEKS OLD.
YES.
OKAY.
FIRST YOU START OFF WITH SOME
RED ONION, DICED TOMATO
AND FRESH CILANTRO.
DO YOU LET THIS SAUTé
FOR A BIT, OR....
YEP. NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE CONCH MEAT,
ADD SOME BROTH THAT WE USED
TO BOIL THE CONCH.
SO YOU FORTIFY THE SAUCE WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF ITS OWN FLAVOR.
OUR CAJUN SEASONING--
LET THAT ALL SIMMER DOWN.
SO WE'RE DONE HERE
WITH THE CONCH.
WE'D ALMOST CALL THAT
A HOT SALSA
THAT'S GONNA GO ON TOP
OF THE FILET?
YEP. ADD SOME
SAUTéED MUSHROOMS.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA THROW THIS
IN THE OVEN ABOUT 30 SECONDS,
LET IT ALL COME TOGETHER.
THAT'S IT.
ADD OUR SAUTéED VEGETABLES.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I WAS
NECESSARILY ANTICIPATING
A MEAL LIKE THAT WHEN I PULLED
UP TO THE, UH, SHANTY.
NICE, MEDIUM RARE
ON THE STEAK.
WELL, THE STEAK'S
JUST ABOUT PERFECT.
THE CONCH--MMM.
IT'S NICE AND TENDER.
YOUR--YOUR MARINATING PROCESS
AND COOKING PROCESS
REALLY MAKES THAT TENDER.
AWESOME.
THAT IS
A BEAUTIFUL-LOOKIN' FILET.
NICE JOB, BUDDY.
COOL.
THE SAUCE IS VERY LIGHT,
VERY FLAVORFUL.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
GOOD MEDIUM-RARE STEAK--
I MEAN, EVERYTHING YOU WANT.
SKILLET ORANGE SALMON,
EXTRA RICE.
WHAT THE KALLIANIS FAMILY
HAS DONE TO THIS PLACE
IN THE LAST THREE YEARS--
LOOK AROUND.
HOW ARE WE DOIN', RAY?
YOU COME HERE.
YOU KNOW EVERYBODY.
SERIOUSLY,
IT'S LIKE HOME.
THAT'S THE WHOLE DEAL HERE.
IT'S A FAMILY.
IT'S COOL--THE WHOLE TOWN.
IT'S AWESOME.
WHISKEY SHRIMP.
THANK YOU.
LOTS OF PEOPLE THINK
THIS IS THEIR RESTAURANT.
I GIVE THIS PLACE A TEN,
THANKS TO ALL THE PEOPLE
THAT COME HERE BECAUSE OF THAT.
(cheering)
UP NEXT...
HOW ABOUT
A LONG ISLAND?
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO CLEVELAND...
IT'S THE GREATEST
ATMOSPHERE EVER.
IT'S SO LAID BACK.
IT'S SO CLEVELAND.
WHERE THIS...
SMOKED SALMON B.L.T.
IS BAR FOOD.
MMM. SALMON HAS NICE SMOKE.
THE SANDWICH IS DOWNTOWN.
NICE JOB, MAN.
WAY TO KNOCK IT OUT.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, IT'S INTERESTING HOW
AREAS AND ENVIRONMENTS CHANGE,
BUT SOME TRIPLE "Ds,"
THEY JUST STAY THE SAME.
I'M HERE IN CLEVELAND, OHIO,
AT A JOINT
THAT OPENED UP
IN THE EARLY 1900s,
HAD THIS GREAT VIEW
OF THIS PARK
THAT WENT RIGHT UP
TO THE WATER'S EDGE.
BUT THEN PROGRESS
AND DEVELOPMENT HAPPENED.
LANDFILL CAME IN
AND THE WATERWAY WAS MOVED,
SO THERE'S NO MORE PARK.
BUT THERE STILL IS
THE PARKVIEW NIGHTCLUB.
BARBECUED ST. LOUIS RIBS
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S A NICE BAR-BAR
WITH REALLY GOOD FOOD.
THERE YOU GO, GIRLS.
THEY HAVE AWESOME FOOD
AND AWESOME DRINKS
AND GREAT PEOPLE.
SO EVERY TIME I TALK
ABOUT COMIN' TO CLEVELAND,
I TALK ABOUT MY CRAZY COUSINS--
MY COUSIN GRETCHEN,
MY COUSIN HEIDI
AND MY COUSIN GREG.
NOW, GRETCH, PORTOBELLO MUSHROOM
SANDWICH IN A JOINT LIKE THIS--
YES, IT'S AWESOME.
FRIED ASPARAGUS IS NOT A NORM
IN THE CLEVELAND BAR SCENE.
HOT ITALIAN CLUB.
IT USED TO BE
A BOOTLEGGIN' RUN
TO WHISKEY ISLAND DURING
THE, UH, PROHIBITION.
I KNOW
HOW TO MAKE THIS.
BUT IT WAS STARTIN'
TO FALL APART
TILL NORM PLONSKI CAME ALONG.
HOW ABOUT
A LONG ISLAND?
I BOUGHT IT IN '93
AND JUST CLEANED IT UP,
PUT SOME GOOD FOOD IN.
THREE PORK TACOS.
BY PUTTIN' SOME REAL COOKS
IN THE KITCHEN,
LIKE RESTAURANT VET
HAROLD KLEIN.
I'VE BEEN COOKIN'
MY WHOLE LIFE.
I WALKED IN HERE
ABOUT ALMOST TWO YEARS AGO,
BRINGIN' A LOT OF MY OWN
CREATIVITY TO THE TABLE.
WITH FAN FAVORITES
LIKE THIS ONE.
SMOKED SALMON B.L.T.
KIND OF A RARE COMBINATION.
IT GOES TOGETHER WELL.
OH, YEAH, WE SMOKE
OUR OWN SALMON.
I'M GONNA CUT THIS
IN THIRDS.
SO YOU DO FAT SIDE UP,
SO THE FAT BASICALLY MELTS
WHILE--
YEAH, IT'S NICE.
WE GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE GLAZE
BEFORE WE DROP IT
INTO THE SMOKER.
OKAY.
WE START OFF WITH
A LITTLE FRESH ORANGE JUICE,
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR,
AND COAT IT UP
WITH A LITTLE HONEY.
WHERE'S THE SMOKER?
SMOKER'S OUT BACK.
SO THIS IS WHAT IT'S ALL DONE
ON? WOW. HOW DO YOU FEED HER?
TO FEED IT UP, I START OFF WITH,
UH, LUMP HARDWOOD CHARCOAL.
JUST POUR THAT RIGHT DOWN
IN THERE.
A MAN AND HIS MACHINE.
FEED IT THE CHARCOAL,
LET IT GET ROLLIN',
HIT IT WITH SOME OF THE, UH,
HICKORY CHIPS FOR THE SMOKE.
GET THAT SALMON, MAN.
SO I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND DROP THIS IN HERE
FOR ABOUT 2, 2 1/2 HOURS.
IT SHOULD BE READY TO GO.
WOW. HOLY SMOKE, BATMAN.
OKAY, THE LITTLE RED BULLET
THAT COULD--IS IT READY?
TAKE A PEEK.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO YOU LET IT COOL DOWN.
AND I WRAP IT
ALL UP INDIVIDUALLY,
SO THEY'RE READY TO USE.
OKAY, BROTHER.
I'LL GET THE LID.
THANK YOU.
PULL OFF
A NICE LITTLE HUNK.
(whistles)
PLACE THIS OVER HERE
ON THE FLATTOP.
HOW BIG IS THE B.L.T.?
NICE-SIZED B.L.T.
YOU GET A LITTLE STEAM ACTION
GOIN' UNDERNEATH.
IN THE MEANTIME,
GRAB A CIABATTA, BUTTER IT UP.
GET A LITTLE TOAST GOIN'.
GRAB OUR BACON.
YOU KNOW, I'M, UH,
PARTIAL TO BACON.
HIT THAT WITH A LITTLE WATER,
GET THAT NICE AND HOT.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S THE PROPER FEEDING
OF BACON I DESERVE.
OH, EASY.
IT'S A RIDICULOUS AMOUNT
OF SALMON, JUST SO YOU KNOW.
PLACE OUR BACON ON TOP.
GIVE IT ONE MORE STEAM.
SALMON SHOULD BE GOOD TO GO.
BRING OUR CIABATTA BREAD OVER.
SCOOP THAT RIGHT UP.
THAT'S TOO MUCH.
OH, NO,
IT'S NEVER TOO MUCH.
A LITTLE TOMATO,
LETTUCE, MAYO--
GO AHEAD AND SLICE IT
RIGHT IN HALF.
WHOA, EVEL KNIEVEL.
SALMON B.L.T.
MMM.
IS THERE ANY ON HERE?
BRO, THE SANDWICH IS DOWNTOWN.
SALMON HAS NICE SMOKE. SALT
OF THE BACON HELPS THE SALMON.
CIABATTA--PERFECT FOR IT.
THIS RIGHT HERE,
THIS IS ALL ABOUT THE SALMON.
NICE JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
WAY TO KNOCK IT OUT.
THE SALMON WAS AWESOME.
NICE, KINDA SMOKY FLAVOR.
FOR IT BEIN' A TAVERN, PROBABLY
HAS SOME OF THE BEST FOOD.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
JUST A PARTY BAR.
(Harold) OH, NO,
IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
(woman) THANK YOU.
IT'S ABOUT GOOD TIMES
AND GOOD FOOD.
TWO JERKED PORK SANDWICHES
WITH FRIES.
CAME IN KIND OF
EXPECTING BAR FOOD,
AND IT WAS
VERY DELICIOUS.
THEY ALWAYS DO A DIFFERENT
SPECIAL EVERY NIGHT.
FISH FRIES ON FRIDAY.
TODAY I DID A SEARED TUNA
WITH A MANGO SALSA.
GET A LOAD
OF THIS GUY.
TACO TUESDAY, YEAH.
(man) HONEY-CHIPOTLE
PORK TACOS.
(woman) IT'S YUMMY.
IT'S GOT, LIKE,
A SPICY-SWEET FLAVOR.
HONEY-CHIPOTLE PORK TACOS.
OKAY.
YES.
I'VE HEARD OF CHIPOTLE
IN TACOS.
WE'RE GONNA DO THE SAUCE
RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE HEARD
THE HONEY-CHIPOTLE.
WE HAVE
OUR CHIPOTLE PEPPERS...
SMOKED JALAPEÑO PEPPERS.
FRESH SQUEEZED
ORANGE JUICE...
A LITTLE
FRESH CILANTRO, OKAY.
AND HONEY.
THAT'S A LOT OF HONEY.
OH, YEAH, IT'S A VERY SMOKY,
HOT, SPICY PEPPER,
SO WE KINDA WANT
TO CALM IT.
OKAY, SO NOW YOU'RE
GONNA PURéE IT UP?
YES. AND THE SAUCE IS DONE.
BEAUTIFUL. NOW WHAT
ARE WE GONNA WORK ON?
THIS IS
A BONE-IN PORK BUTT.
FIRST I'M GONNA INSERT
A COUPLE SLITS.
GONNA STUFF SOME FRESH CLOVES
OF GARLIC DOWN INTO IT.
I LIKE THIS.
I'M GONNA START OUT
WITH A RUB NOW,
WHICH I DO ONE BY ONE.
IT'LL BE A LITTLE ONION POWDER.
NOW WHY NOT RUB 'EM
ALL TOGETHER?
I JUST LIKE TO WORK
EVERY INGREDIENT BY HAND.
I'LL LET YOU DO THIS
ON YOUR SHOW.
NEXT A LITTLE
CAJUN SEASONING,
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER,
JUST A LITTLE SEASONING SALT
AND A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THAT I GOT THIS
ALL RUBBED DOWN,
THROWN IN ITS OWN CONTAINER,
I'M GONNA LET THIS SIT
FOR 24 HOURS BEFORE IT HITS
THE SMOKER. ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL LET THIS COOK
FOR ABOUT SIX TO SEVEN HOURS.
PULL IT OUT, COOL IT DOWN,
THEN SHRED IT APART.
AND THERE WE GO.
(whistles)
WE ARE GOOD TO GO,
JUICES RUNNING CLEAR.
YEAH.
AND BRING IT UP, THROW 'EM
IN OUR PAN, TAKE THIS UP INSIDE.
SO PORK BUTT IS COOLED DOWN
A LITTLE BIT--
GET AFTER IT, WOLVERINE.
ALL RIGHT.
WOW, YOU REALLY DO
GET AFTER IT.
OH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT GARLIC.
YEAH, IT'S GOOD.
THAT'S GREAT. LOOK AT THAT--
JUST LIKE BUTTER.
OH, YEAH, IT'S TENDER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BONE FALLS RIGHT OUT--
GOOD-LOOKIN', MAN.
NOW WE'VE GOT OUR PORK
THAT WE JUST PULLED.
HOW MANY TACOS
AM I HAVIN'?
JUST TWO. WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND HIT IT WITH A LITTLE STEAM.
TAKE 2 OF THOSE
6-INCH FLOUR TORTILLAS,
TOAST 'EM UP QUESADILLA-STYLE
WITH A LITTLE MELTED CHEDDAR.
I LIKE THIS MANEUVER.
THROW A LITTLE BIT OF
THE HONEY-CHIPOTLE SAUCE ON IT.
MIX ALL THIS UP,
PUT A LITTLE CRISP ON IT.
THEN GO AHEAD AND STEAM IT UP
ONE MORE TIME.
LETTIN' THAT SAUCE COOK RIGHT IN
AND ABSORB RIGHT INTO THE PORK.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT
JUST "ZORB" RIGHT IN?
YEAH, IT'S JUST GONNA
ABSORB RIGHT IN.
IT'S GONNA "ZORB" RIGHT IN.
IT'S NEW CLEVELAND TALK.
OH, YEAH.
I LIKE WHEN IT STARTS
CRUSTIN' UP THERE.
IT'S DONE "ZORBING"?
YES. ADD A LITTLE
ROMAINE LETTUCE INTO IT.
DON'T GO GETTIN'
ALL CALIFORNIA ON ME.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND ADD A LITTLE FRESH PICO
AND A LITTLE SOUR CREAM.
WHAT DO YOU PUT
IN THE PICO DE GALLO?
JALAPEÑOS, GARLIC,
RED WINE VINEGAR,
ALL YOUR BASICS.
(chuckling)
DUDE, YOU DIDN'T GO
ANYWHERE WRONG ON THIS.
THE MELTED CHEESE,
THE SMOKY PORK,
THE HEAT OF THE CHIPOTLES,
THE FRESHNESS OF THE PICO,
COOL IT DOWN
WITH THE SOUR CREAM.
I'LL BE BACK ON TUESDAY
AND WEDNESDAY...
AWESOME.
AND THURSDAY.
THE CHIPOTLE
IS REALLY GOOD,
AND THE PORK IS
INCREDIBLY TENDER.
IT'S DELICIOUS--
GREAT SMOKINESS TO IT.
IT'S KIND OF FUN TO HAVE
A TWIST ON A TACO.
JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO EAT.
SEARED TUNA
WITH CARIBBEAN FRIES.
WHEN YOU WALK IN HERE,
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA BE
WELCOMED BY FRIENDS.
ENJOY.
THANKS.
THE GREATEST ATMOSPHERE EVER.
IT'S SO LAID BACK.
IT'S SO CLEVELAND.
SMOKED SALMON B.L.T.
WHEN THEY COME IN AND THEY GET
THE FOOD, IT'S LIKE, "WOW.
WE DIDN'T EXPECT THIS."
CONGRATULATIONS.
NICE PLACE.
THANK YOU.
CRAZY PLACE.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADIN'
TO WESTERN NEW YORK...
BRUISER, MEDIUM RARE.
WHERE THEY'RE
DOIN' BURGERS...
WE'RE REALLY GONNA PUT LETTUCE
AND TOMATO IN THIS.
(woman) YES, WE ARE.
YOU CAN EAT WITH A SPOON.
CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
MMM, THAT IS SO DELICIOUS.
YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES IT?
THE LETTUCE.
HERE I AM--
EAST AMHERST, NEW YORK,
ABOUT 20 MILES
FROM DOWNTOWN BUFFALO,
TO VISIT A PLACE THAT'S BEEN
VOTED BEST BURGERS
THREE YEARS RUNNING.
NOW THAT'S ENOUGH OF A REASON
TO VISIT A JOINT, RIGHT?
BUT GET THIS--
THERE'S A KICKER.
THIS PLACE WAS ACTUALLY
THE OLD HUNTING LODGE
FOR GROVER CLEVELAND--
YOU KNOW, GROVER CLEVELAND,
THE PRESIDENT.
ISN'T THAT COOL?
HERE WE ARE AT GROVER'S.
COMIN' OUT
UP ON A CHEDDAR BURGER.
HUGE--IT'S LIKE
A SIRLOIN ON A BUN.
BIG BRUISER.
THAT IS A BIG BURGER, YES.
STEAK SANDWICH WITH ONIONS
AND PEPPERS--FANTASTIC.
MEDIUM WINGS.
PARMESAN CHEESE
REALLY MELLOWS OUT THE HEAT.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
ALL THAT?
YOUR SHOWS.
ANYTHING GEORGINA
HAS ON THE MENU IS GOOD.
THAT'D BE
GEORGINA HARTMAN.
CHEDDAR CHEESEBURGER
MEDIUM.
WELL, I WAS WORKING
IN THE KITCHEN WHEN I WAS 15.
BACK WHEN HER MOM JOANIE
OPENED THE PLACE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
WELL, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR COMING AGAIN.
WERE THE BURGERS
ALWAYS THE SIZE OF, UH...
W-WE ALWAYS DID.
MANHOLE COVERS?
MEDIUM-WELL
CATTLEMAN BURGER.
THE CATTLEMAN IS BACON,
BARBECUE, CHEDDAR CHEESE.
THEN WE HAVE
SWISS MUSHROOM.
AND THEIR BESTSELLER...
(woman) THE BRUISER.
(Guy) THE BRUISER?
JUICY--THE ONIONS ARE GREAT.
I MEAN, IT IS GOOD.
THIS IS AN 80-20...
80-20.
CERTIFIED ANGUS GROUND BEEF.
WE DON'T SEASON IT.
WE DON'T PUT ANYTHING ON IT.
I'M JUST GONNA GRAB A BALL HERE.
WHAT SIZE PATTY
ARE WE MAKIN'?
ABOUT 12 OUNCES
FOR THE BRUISER BURGER.
THE SIZE OF A BRAIN.
WE TEND TO GIVE MORE
THAN WE'RE SUPPOSED TO.
DO YOU GIVE THEM A FRIES
OR T-SHIRT OR ANYTHING
IF THEY FINISH IT?
WE'VE HAD A COUPLE PEOPLE
EAT TWO OF THESE,
AND IT'S ALWAYS THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE ABOUT MY SIZE,
ABOUT THAT BIG.
MM-HMM.
IT'S THAT HIGH METABOLISM.
THAT'S RIGHT. SO THAT LOOKS
PRETTY GOOD TO ME RIGHT NOW.
I WANT YOU GUYS
TO HEAR THIS SOUND.
(loud thump)
(whispers)
THAT'S SCARY.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTé SOME ONIONS
WITH THIS OIL, SO IT'S NOT DRY,
AND WE DON'T STICK.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE ONIONS ON.
I'M JUST GONNA GRAB
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER HERE.
SALT AND PEPPER--
LET THOSE BROWN UP.
NOW WE CAN PUT
THE BURGER ON.
(normal voice)
DROP IT FROM WAY UP
AND LET IT JUST GO WHACK!
HOW LONG DOES THAT TAKE
TO COOK THAT?
WELL, WE WANT MEDIUM RARE,
SO I'M GONNA GUESSTIMATE
PROBABLY ABOUT THREE TO FOUR
ON EACH SIDE.
PUT A LITTLE BUTTER
ON THE BUN.
WOW.
DO A LITTLE FLIP HERE. NOW
I'M GONNA GET A LITTLE CAJUN.
NOW WHAT'S IN
THE CAJUN SPICE?
CAYENNE, PAPRIKA,
BLACK PEPPER
AND GARLIC.
GOT IT.
PUT THE ONIONS ON TOP.
NOW THE ROQUEFORT
CRUMBLY BLUE CHEESE.
AT GROVER'S
WE OVERDO EVERYTHING.
PUT THAT ON TOP FOR A LITTLE
QUICK STEAM UP HERE.
I LIKE IT.
AND IN ONE MINUTE, YOU'RE
GONNA BE EATING THE BRUISER.
YOU WANT ME TO PUT
A NAPKIN ON?
YOU HAVE, LIKE, A BED SHEET
OR SOMETHIN' HERE
THAT'S AVAILABLE.
(laughs)
WOW, THAT'S A BIG BURGER. THIS
IS THE BEST PART ABOUT THIS.
FLATTOPS HAVE A VERY DISTINCT
STYLE ABOUT THEM,
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU GOT
A GOOD AMOUNT OF FAT.
IT CREATES
THIS CRUNCHY TEXTURE.
I LIKE ROQUEFORT CHEESE.
I LIKE ONIONS,
BUT THERE'S NO WAY
I COULD EAT THAT WHOLE THING.
THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE THIS BIG--
THOSE ARE THE PEOPLE
THAT CAN EAT TWO.
ABSOLUTELY IMPOSSIBLE.
IS THAT ENOUGH BURGER? I MEAN,
YOU GUYS ARE FROM TEXAS.
WAY TOO MUCH FOR ME,
BUT IT IS EXCELLENT.
PUTTIN' ON A BRUISER.
AND THAT'S ONLY ONE OF A DOZEN
THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT.
HERE'S YOUR BLUE BURGER.
A LOT OF BEEF, A LOT OF
BLUE CHEESE--RIGHT ON THE MONEY.
AND YOUR CHEESEBURGER.
THEIR BURGERS ARE HUGE.
THEY'RE JUICY.
IT'S REALLY JUST
AN AMAZING BURGER PLACE.
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR...
(woman) 18 YEARS.
FOR THE BURGERS...
COMIN' DOWN WITH BACON.
AND A WHOLE MENU
OF HOMEMADE COMFORT FOOD.
MEAT LOAF AND FRIES.
WE ALWAYS HAVE THE WINGS.
SINGLE ORDER
OF MEDIUM WINGS.
AND A GET A LOAD
OF THIS ONE...
CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
YEP, CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
IT'S JUST WHAT IT SAYS
IT IS--
CHEESE BROTH WITH LARGE CHUNKS
OF BURGER IN IT. EXCELLENT.
I GOT A BOWL
OF CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
NOT HAVING TO WORRY ABOUT THE
BUN AND ALL THAT KIND OF STUFF,
IT'S JUST FANTASTIC.
TASTES LIKE A CHEESEBURGER
IN A BOWL.
OKAY, NOW I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF THAT.
YEAH.
FIRST THING WE DO IS PUT IN
THE WONDERFUL BUTTER.
LET THIS SOFTEN UP A TAD.
ALL RIGHT, NOW YOU CAN GIVE ME
THE ONIONS.
GOT IT?
WE HAVE TO WAIT NOW
FOR THESE TO SWEAT OUT.
SWEAT THOSE DOWN,
TURN 'EM TRANSLUCENT.
AND NOW HERE'S THE NEW BURGER
THAT THEY'RE SERVING
HERE AT GROVER'S--
THIS IS THE 4-POUNDER.
(laughs)
SEE, THIS IS A GREAT MOVE.
YOU GET SOME OF
THAT CHARRED TEXTURE
THAT YOU GET ON A FLATTOP.
YEAH.
SO DEGLAZE THE PAN.
WITH WATER.
AND THEN I'M GONNA PUT
MY CHICKEN BASE IN THERE.
NEXT, HALF-AND-HALF.
OKAY.
COULD YOU PASS
THE SLURRY, PLEASE?
IS THAT A FLOUR SLURRY?
YES, FLOUR AND WATER.
NOW WE'LL PUT IN
THE CHEESE SAUCE.
I THOUGHT IT WAS MUSTARD.
AND I'M LIKE, "I DON'T KNOW
HOW POSSIBLY YOU COULD PUT
THAT MUCH MUSTARD INTO IT."
AND YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS MUSTARD?
WHO MADE THIS RECIPE UP?
ACTUALLY, I DID.
I JUST PLAYED WITH IT,
AND THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED.
NOW WE PUT IN
THAT WONDERFUL BURGER.
NEXT, LETTUCE.
WE'RE REALLY GONNA PUT LETTUCE
AND TOMATO IN THERE?
YES, WE ARE.
IS THERE LETTUCE
ON A CHEESEBURGER?
WELL, I KNOW THERE IS,
BUT I'M JUST--
YEAH!
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS.
AND LASTLY, THE TOMATOES.
WE MIX IT ALL TOGETHER,
AND WE'RE ALL DONE.
READY TO TASTE IT.
THIS IS CRAZY.
IT SMELLS LIKE CHEESEBURGER.
HERE'S TO YOU!
NO WAY!
THIS IS--NO KIDDING--
LIQUID CHEESEBURGER.
SUPER FLAVOR. I MEAN,
THIS IS REALLY AWESOME.
NOT TOO CHEESY,
RIGHT SIZE OF TOMATO--MMM!
AND YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES IT?
THE LETTUCE,
THAT LITTLE BIT
OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
GLAD YOU'RE ENJOYING IT.
THIS IS, LIKE, MY 19th SPOONFUL,
BUT IT'S SO DELICIOUS.
I LOVE IT, AND IT'S WONDERFUL.
ONE CUP
OF CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
(Guy) LOOK AT
THAT MONSTER BITE.
WHAT DO YOU GOT FOR ME?
2 THUMBS UP?
YOU HEARD IT RIGHT FROM HIM.
AND THERE'S
THE CHEESEBURGER SOUP FOR YOU.
I DON'T THINK
WE COULD EVER COPY THIS.
WE SPLIT IT, IF YOU WANT
TO HAVE SOME WINGS, TOO.
MEDIUM WINGS.
INVENTED IN BUFFALO,
BUT GROVER'S HAS TAKEN IT
TO A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL.
OUT OF EVERYTHING,
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE?
I'M GONNA HAVE
TO SAY THE WINGS.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
WOW, WOW, WOW, WOW!
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
OKAY, ONE BRUISER, MEDIUM,
HAMBURGER.
AT GROVER'S
IN EAST AMHERST, NEW YORK...
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
JOANIE HARTMAN
AND HER DAUGHTER GEORGINA
ARE CRANKIN' OUT
THE BURGERS...
CHEDDAR BURGER.
BIG PLATES
OF COMFORT FOOD...
MEAT LOAF AND FRIES.
AND, HEY, SINCE THEY'RE
JUST 20 MILES FROM BUFFALO...
WINGS OFF!
THEY'RE DOING
WHAT THEY GOTTA DO.
INVENTED IN BUFFALO,
BUT GROVER'S HAS TAKEN IT
TO A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL.
BIGGER, CRISPIER
AND TASTIER.
THEY'RE BIG WINGS. THESE ARE
NOT LITTLE PIGEON WINGS
THAT YOU SEE SOME PLACES
WHEN YOU GO OUT.
GARLIC WINGS.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER HAD
GARLIC WINGS BEFORE.
THESE ARE ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
GARLIC PARMESAN
BUFFALO WINGS.
OKAY.
THERE'S TEN TO AN ORDER.
WOW, PTERODACTYL WING.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GET 'EM STARTED.
AND HOW HOT'S THE FRYER?
ABOUT 400 DEGREES.
AND YOU GO FROM RAW
ALL THE TIME?
ALWAYS.
LET 'EM GO FOR 14 TO 15 MINUTES,
'CAUSE I LIKE THAT SKIN
TO BE CRUNCHY
WHEN I GET IN THERE.
YEAH, I WANT SOME CRUNCH.
AND I ALSO LIKE TO RENDER DOWN
THE FAT INSIDE.
YOU GOT IT.
OKAY, SO WHEN DO WE
MAKE THE SAUCE?
WE CAN START MAKING IT NOW.
WE'RE READY, OKAY?
I MEASURED
ABOUT THAT MUCH BUTTER!
BUTTER.
THIS IS FRESH GARLIC
THAT WE CHOP IN ADVANCE,
THEN A LITTLE
GRATED PARMESAN CHEESE,
THEN THE BUFFALO HOT SAUCE.
I LIKE WHERE YOU WENT
WITH THIS.
MY MOUTH'S STARTING
TO WATER ALREADY.
AND NOW WE MIX IT UP.
OKAY, ARE THESE
BAD BOYS READY?
I THINK SO.
SHAKE 'EM UP. I DON'T LIKE 'EM
TO STICK TOGETHER,
WHICH THEY SOMETIMES DO.
OKAY, LET'S GRAB OUR SAUCE.
DUMP 'EM IN THERE.
SO YOU WANT TO GIVE 'EM FLAVOR
AND COAT 'EM REAL NICE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE READY.
THEN YOU POUR
ALL THAT SAUCE ON TOP?
DEPENDS ON HOW SAUCY
YOU LIKE THEM.
OH, I'M SAUCY.
YOU'RE SAUCY, SO JUST
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT.
I DON'T WANT
TO DO TOO MUCH.
LOOK AT THAT.
GREAT SKIN,
GREAT RENDERING DOWN.
MMM!
WOW, WOW, WOW, WOW!
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
GOOD DEAL.
SUPER CRUNCH-ALISTIC,
COOKED JUST HOW I LIKE IT.
LOOK AT THAT LITTLE NUGGET
RIGHT THERE. SEE ALL THE FRIED?
GET THE SWEETNESS OF THE BUTTER
AND THE PARMESAN CHEESE,
LITTLE BITE
OF THE GARLIC. MMM!
I'D ONLY KIND OF CALL IT
A "HINT" OF HEAT.
THAT'S A GREAT MIXTURE.
BOY, IS THAT GOOD.
YOUR GARLIC PARMESAN WINGS.
REALLY TENDER, REALLY CRISPY,
WHICH IS REALLY NICE.
(man) GOOD FLAVOR, NICE GARLIC,
GOOD PARMESAN,
NICE MEATY WING.
SINGLE ORDER OF WINGS.
(bell dings)
WE LIKE THE WINGS,
LIKE EVERYBODY.
IT'S AN EXCELLENT PLACE.
BRUISER, MEDIUM RARE.
THEY PUT A LOT MORE EFFORT
INTO THEIR COOKING.
CATTLEMAN CHICKEN.
DOESN'T MATTER,
IT'S ALL GOOD.
YEAH.
THIS IS OUR SPOT.
CHEESEBURGER SOUP.
EVERY TIME WE GO TO GROVER'S,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
I'M SO HAPPY THAT YOU CAME.
I HOPE YOU ENJOYED EVERYTHING.
VERY COMFORTABLE. YOU FEEL
LIKE HOME COMING HERE.
LADIES, I GOTTA TELL YOU,
WE HAD A BLAST.
I THINK WHEN YOU COME DOWN HERE,
YOU'D BETTER BRING AN APPETITE.
AND THAT CHEESEBURGER SOUP--
UH-HUH.
SO I TOLD YOU, IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THEY GOT ALLIGATOR.
THEY GOT CORN DOGS.
THEY GOT ALL THOSE THINGS.
HANG ON A SECOND.
DID YOU FALL
RIGHT IN THE CORN DOG?
THEY GOT NO CORN DOGS.
YOU EPICUREAN, YOU.