HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
NOW THAT'S MAC AND CHEESE
GONE WILD, HUH?
ONLY AT THIS JOINT.
MMM.
IN PORTLAND, OREGON,
WHERE A BARBECUE DUDE
IS DOING FRESH TROUT...
IT'S JUST MOIST.
IT FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
AND LAMB RIBS...
UNUSUAL, BUT IT'S SO GOOD.
ON A RIG OF HIS OWN.
YOU BUILT THE BARBECUE?
YEP.
IN DEERFIELD BEACH, FLORIDA...
ONE DOZEN OYSTERS,
PICK IT UP!
IF IT'S NOT FRESH,
YOU'RE NOT CARRYING IT.
WE AIN'T HAVING IT.
WHERE THE HOUSE SPECIALTY IS
SOMETHING CALLED WHALE JUICE.
AMAZING, I LOVE IT.
AND FOLKS ARE PACKING IN
FOR A CLASSIC...
OYSTER ROCKEFELLER.
DONE THEIR WAY.
TOMATO?
TOMATO, BUDDY,
I'M TELLING YA.
AND IN IDAHO,
A NEW SPIN...
MMM.
ON DRIVE-IN DINING.
FABULOUS.
THE NASTY NACHOS--
MESSY BUT TOTALLY WORTH IT.
THE CHILI MAC,
IT'S CLASSIC.
AND MESQUITE-GRILLED
BURGERS...
WHAT CAN I PUT ON IT?
JUST ABOUT
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
THEY'RE PILIN' HIGH.
MMM, GOOD BURGER
COOKED THE RIGHT WAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
CERTAIN REGIONS
OF THE COUNTRY
MAKE YOU THINK
ABOUT CERTAIN KINDS OF FOOD,
LIKE WHEN YOU'RE
CLOSE TO THE COAST,
USUALLY THINKING SEAFOOD.
HERE I AM IN PORTLAND, OREGON,
SURROUNDED BY SEAFOOD.
I'M NOT FEELING
LIKE SEAFOOD TODAY.
THINKING ABOUT BARBECUE,
SPECIFICALLY TEXAS BARBECUE.
NOW MY COUSIN PAUL
LIVES HERE,
AND HE SAYS HE'S HEARD ABOUT
A PLACE CALLED PODNAH'S.
SO I FIGURE
I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
I GOT A FULL RACK
OF RIBS.
REALLY BIG FLAVORS.
MOIST, SMOKY, DELICIOUS.
WE ALWAYS
COME FOR THE RIBS.
REALLY AUTHENTIC
TEXAS BARBECUE.
IT'S JUST ONE OF THOSE THINGS
I GREW UP WITH.
THEN RODNEY MUIRHEAD
LEFT THE LONE STAR STATE...
TABLE EIGHT.
AND STARTED COOKING
IN NEW YORK CITY.
WENT TO
THE FRENCH CULINARY INSTITUTE
AND WORKED IN
A COUPLE OF RESTAURANTS THERE.
BUT THEN HE LEFT THE BIZ FOR
A HIGH-TECH JOB IN PORTLAND...
I WASN'T PLANNING ON
OPENING A RESTAURANT AT ALL.
TILL HE GOT LAID OFF
AND WENT BACK TO HIS ROOTS.
WAS THERE ANYONE
SPECIFIC IN YOUR LIFE
THAT TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO BARBECUE?
IT WAS MY GRANDFATHER.
HE WAS A BUTCHER.
HIS NICKNAME WAS PODNAH.
WHAT'S UP, PODNAH?
SO THAT'S WHY
I NAMED IT AFTER--EXACTLY.
NICE.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
WHERE'D YOU BUY
THE BARBECUE?
I BUILT IT.
YOU BUILT THE BARBECUE.
YEAH.
AND IT'S CRANKING OUT MORE
THAN 30 TONS OF 'CUE A YEAR,
FROM SPARE RIBS
AND CHICKEN...
ABSOLUTELY SUCCULENT
AND DELICIOUS.
TO PULLED PORK
AND CLASSIC TEXAS BRISKET.
THE BRISKET IS AMAZING.
GOOD SMOKY FLAVOR,
REAL TENDER.
THAT'S A BIG'N.
THAT IS A LARGE BRISKET.
TYRANNOSAURUS BEEF.
I ASSUME WE'RE RUBBING IT.
PRETTY SIMPLE TEXAS DRY RUB--
BLACK PEPPER...
FRESH CRACKED?
YES, A LOT
OF BLACK PEPPER.
PEPPER, SALT AND CAYENNE.
THAT'S IT.
WOW, NOW ARE WE JUST
COLORING IT WITH THE CAYENNE?
YEAH, JUST
A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA
TRIM THIS DOWN?
ALL THE TOP FAT'S
GONNA STAY ON.
THERE'S JUST ONE PIECE
ON THE BOTTOM THAT COMES OFF.
TRY TO JUST GET
THIS LUMP OF FAT OUT.
WOW, YOU SHOULD GO GET
A LITTLE JOB ON "NIP/TUCK."
DO YOU LET THIS SET UP
FOR A LITTLE BIT?
IT DOES SET
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA LET
THIS GO IN THE SMOKER?
THIS GOES
EIGHT TO TEN HOURS.
WHAT DO
WE RUN IT AT, 225?
I RUN IT ABOUT 250.
WOW, TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
WHOO, SLICE ME
OFF SOME, CAP'N.
A LITTLE BARK ON THERE.
LOOK AT THE SMOKE RING ON THAT.
MMM, GOOD RUB, MAN.
REAL ELABORATE RUB.
I REALLY THINK
THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
WITH THE FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
YEAH, DEFINITELY.
NOW HOW MANY BRISKETS
WILL YOU RUN IN A DAY?
ON BUSIER WEEKEND DAYS,
I COOK ABOUT SIX.
FOR THE SANDWICHES,
THE DINNERS
AND SOMETHING
THEY'RE CALLING PLATO TEJANO--
THE TEXAS PLATE.
NICE BEEF BRISKET, PINTO BEANS,
A COUPLE FLOUR TORTILLAS.
AND THROW IN SOME
SCRATCH-MADE SALSA.
WE'RE USING ANAHEIMS
AND JALAPEÑOS.
AND NOW WHAT
ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I TAKE A TORCH
AND GET 'EM REALLY BLACK.
SO YOU DON'T
JUST SIT HERE
AND LET 'EM FLOP AROUND
ON THE GRILL.
NO, WE SPEED IT
UP A LITTLE.
THEY STAY OUT HERE
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
THEN WE STEAM 'EM
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES MORE.
AND THEN
TAKE THE SKINS OFF,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE SALSA WITH IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
DIG IT.
PUT A LITTLE WATER
IN THE BLENDER.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
THIS RECIPE FROM?
THIS IS MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW'S RECIPE.
SO I CAN'T MESS IT UP.
YEAH.
TOMATOES AND SOME PEPPERS.
BETTER NOT COMPLAIN
ABOUT IT, EITHER.
SALT.
IT'S REALLY EXACT
ON THE MEASUREMENT.
YEAH, OH, DEFINITELY.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
I'M PRETTY
MUCH GONNA HAVE TO TRY THAT.
NOW DO YOU LET
THE FLAVORS MARRY FOR A DAY?
IF IT SETS FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
IT GETS A LITTLE BETTER.
NICE, FRESH, A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT, NICE JOB.
DO YOU PICK AND EAT
OR DO YOU PILE IT ON?
WHAT DO YOU DO?
YEAH, I TEAR OFF
A QUARTER LIKE THAT.
MMM, I THINK THAT THE SALSA
TOTALLY ACCENTUATES IT.
SALSA GETS BETTER
BY THE MINUTE.
YEAH.
THE MOTHER-IN-LAW
WILL BE HAPPY WITH YOU NOW.
I THINK YOU'RE MORE INTERESTED
IN THE MOTHER-IN-LAW BEING HAPPY
WITH YOU THAN YOU ARE
WITH HER BEING HAPPY WITH ME.
GOOD POINT.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY NICE.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT'S THE BEST BEEF BRISKET
I'VE EVER HAD.
AARON,
I GOT TABLE TEN,
BRISKET SANDWICH
AND PULLED PORK COMBO.
I GREW UP IN TEXAS,
FOUND THIS PLACE AND...
YOU'RE HOME.
DON'T EAT ANYWHERE ELSE.
THERE'S JUST
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
I'VE SORT OF WORKED MY WAY UP
AND DOWN THE MENU--
BRISKET, RIBS.
NORMALLY IT'S PORK OR BEEF,
BUT THE LAMB IS GOOD.
CENTRAL TEXAS
LAMB RIBS.
WHY LAMB RIB?
THERE'S ONE TOWN
IN CENTRAL TEXAS NAMED GONZALES.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
I'VE EVER SEEN 'EM.
AND THEY'RE JUST AMAZING.
THIS I AM DYING TO TRY.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
SALT AND PEPPER AGAIN,
HEAVY ON THE PEPPER.
A LITTLE GRANULATED GARLIC
COMING UP.
YEP.
AND THAT'S GOTTA BE COMINO.
YEAH, CUMIN.
AND HOW LONG YOU BEEN SERVING
THIS HERE AT THE RESTAURANT?
SINCE WE OPENED.
THIS IS ONE OF THE MORE POPULAR
THINGS, AND WE'RE PRETTY LUCKY
WE HAVE A GUY THAT WE GET
THIS LAMB FROM--CATTAIL CREEK.
HE'S LOCAL, BUT HE SUPPLIES
SOME OF THE BEST RESTAURANTS
IN THE COUNTRY, SO...
THAT'S BASICALLY IT.
THEY WOULD LOVE YOU ON MY SHOW
"GUY'S BIG BITE."
I ALWAYS GET COMPLAINTS--
"TOO MANY INGREDIENTS!"
YOU--OKAY, FOUR.
SALT AND PEPPER. YEAH.
THESE GO FOR
ABOUT THREE TO FOUR HOURS.
AT 250.
ABOUT 250, YEAH.
MMM!
THIS ONE'S REALLY MEATY.
MMM. IT DOESN'T SUCK.
LOOK AT THAT.
NO SAUCE, NO NADA.
THAT'S IT,
JUST LIKE THIS.
LOOK AT ALL THE MEAT IN THERE.
REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
YEAH.
AND GOOD FAT. I MEAN, THAT FAT
JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
YEAH.
THIS IS A FIRST, MAN.
ONLY ON TRIPLE "D."
LAMB RIBS.
REALLY GOOD, UNUSUAL,
BUT IT'S SO GOOD.
AND TALK ABOUT UNUSUAL...
TABLE 11,
PORK RIBS AND TROUT.
TROUT?
TROUT ARE JUST
SO POPULAR UP HERE,
AND IT'S
GOOD SMOKED, SO...
WHY NOT?
SO IT'S JUST A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER, THEN PARSLEY,
SOME LEMON SLICES.
(whistles)
AND FOLD IT OVER.
OKAY, SO YOU ARE
SMOKING IT WITH THE SKIN,
BECAUSE OTHERWISE THAT FLESH
WOULD JUST ABSORB THAT SMOKE
SO FAST, YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE ANY FISH FLAVOR.
AND HOW LONG ARE
THESE GONNA GO ON FOR?
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
I TURN IT AT ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
LET ME GET INTO ONE OF THESE.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THIS IS LIKE
A FRENCH SMOKE,
YOU KNOW, WHERE IT'S
REALLY LIGHTLY DONE.
I THINK THAT SKIN
IS WHAT PROTECTS IT.
YOU CAN SEE THE BIG SMOKE RIGHT
IN THERE. LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THAT'S A CLASSY MOVE
RIGHT THERE, MAN.
THANK YOU.
(man) IT'S COOKED PERFECTLY.
IT'S JUST MOIST.
IT FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
YOU CAN EAT ANYTHING HERE.
IT'LL BE GREAT. YOU'LL BE HAPPY.
WE GOT A RACK AND A PULLED PORK
SANDWICH WITH SLAW.
THIS IS HEAD AND SHOULDERS
ABOVE THE REST.
THIS PREVAILS.
YEAH.
AND I'LL
DEFINITELY BE BACK.
I BRING MY FRIENDS, TOO.
LOVE TO SEE
THESE STORIES, MAN.
THAT'S THE WHOLE THING
WE LOVE ABOUT TRIPLE "D,"
IS FINDING THE REAL DEAL APPEAL
TO DOING IT YOUR OWN WAY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
GOOD JOINT.
YES.
GOOD LAMB RIBS.
UP NEXT...
A POUND OF LARGE STONE.
WE'RE HEADING EAST.
THAT'S HOW I SHUCK.
TO A SEAFOOD JOINT...
THE BEST OF DEERFIELD.
THAT'S A LOCAL LEGEND.
MMM, I GUESS
YOU GOTTA COME TO FLORIDA
TO GET A SANDWICH
LIKE THAT.
YES, YOU DO.
WHEN YOU'RE CRUISING THE COASTAL
STATES LIKE, YOU KNOW,
CALIFORNIA OR FLORIDA,
THERE'S USUALLY TWO THINGS
PEOPLE ARE LOOKING FOR--
THAT'S GOOD BEACHES
AND GREAT SEAFOOD.
AND FROM WHAT
THE LOCALS TELL US,
WE FOUND BOTH HERE
AT THE WHALE'S RIB RESTAURANT
IN DEERFIELD BEACH, FLORIDA.
POUND OF LARGE STONES.
STEAMED IPSWICH.
WE'RE ABOUT 100 YARDS
FROM THE OCEAN.
THE FISH
IS ALWAYS FRESH, ALWAYS.
MUSSELS IN GARLIC BUTTER.
THE ROCK SHRIMP
IS THE BEST.
BEST CLAM CHOWDER
SINCE I WAS EIGHT YEARS OLD.
MADE THE SAME WAY SINCE OWNER
DALE STEVENSON...
WHO HAD THE OYSTERS?
OPENED THIS JOINT
ALMOST 30 YEARS AGO.
A LOT OF REPEAT BUSINESS FROM
PEOPLE WHEN THEY WERE KIDS.
NOW THEY'RE 30 YEARS OLD.
THEY'RE COMING BACK
WITH THEIR KIDS.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR 20 SOME-ODD YEARS.
IT'S EXACTLY THE SAME.
WITH A STAFF THAT KEEPS
ON COMING BACK, TOO.
HOW MANY YEARS?
19.
WHAT'D YOU DO,
START IN KINDERGARTEN?
YEAH. OH, I LOVE YOU.
AND KITCHEN MANAGER
JOHN KEENER...
WE GOT 2 DOZEN RAW OYSTERS
GOING TO THE BAR SIDE.
HE'S BEEN HERE SINCE '93.
IF IT'S NOT FRESH.
YOU'RE NOT CARRYING IT.
WE AIN'T HAVING IT.
I LIKE THE ATTITUDE.
I'VE GOT A MEDIUM
AND LARGE STONE CRAB HERE.
THEY ARE
IN SEASON RIGHT NOW.
AWESOME CRAB CAKES.
YOU HAVEN'T
EVEN BITTEN INTO IT YET.
YEAH, I HAD ONE EARLIER.
OH, YOU DID?
THIS IS MY SECOND PLATE.
ONE DOZEN OYSTERS,
PICK IT UP!
I'VE HAD OYSTERS
BUT NOT FRESH LIKE THIS.
IN THE SHELL...
THAT'S HOW I SHUCK.
BAKED WITH PARMESAN,
AND THIS CLASSIC...
OYSTER ROCKEFELLER.
DONE THE WHALE'S RIB WAY.
VERY GOOD
WITH THE TOMATO.
WITH A TOMATO SLAB.
IS THAT NORMAL?
IT'S NORMAL FOR THEM.
FIRST OF ALL, WHAT TYPE
OF OYSTERS ARE WE ROCKING OUT?
FROM THE GULF OF MEXICO.
ARE THEY FRESH?
OH, DEFINITELY.
DO YOU SHUCK 'EM HERE?
YES, SIR.
STEAMED SPINACH HERE.
PRESSED THE WATER
OUT OF IT.
DEFINITELY, YOU DON'T
WANT SOUP ON YOUR OYSTERS.
GIVE IT A COARSE CHOP.
GO IN THE BOWL WITH IT.
NOT STARTING OUT
WITH THE FROZEN.
OKAY, SO FRESH
SPINACH STEAMED.
NOPE. DICED ONION.
ITALIAN BREADCRUMBS.
OKAY.
PARMESAN CHEESE,
TEASPOON OF CAYENNE PEPPER.
SUPPOSED TO SAY CAY-OHN.
CAY-OHN PEPPER.
ABOUT AN OUNCE
OF BLACK PEPPER, WHITE WINE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WOW, SO THAT'S
VERY SPINACHY.
VERY MUCH SO. WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE ROCKEFELLER MIX
ON TOP OF THE OYSTER
ON THE HALF SHELL.
A LITTLE TRAY
WRAPPED IN TINFOIL
SO YOU DON'T
HAVE TO SCRUB IT TOO HARD.
GO EASY
ON THE DISHWASHERS.
HOLY PINCH, POPEYE.
SLICE OF TOMATO,
LITTLE PROVOLONE CHEESE.
TOMATO.
TOMATO, YEAH. A LITTLE PARM
ON TOP JUST TO BROWN IT UP.
I HAVE NEVER
SEEN IT MADE THIS WAY.
THIS IS THE MOST UNIQUE.
WELCOME TO DEERFIELD BEACH.
OKAY.
IN THE OVEN SHE GOES.
SO THEY'RE GONNA GO DOWN
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
A LITTLE UNDER
TEN MINUTES.
NICE AND BUBBLY.
YEP.
TOMATO.
TOMATO, BUDDY, I'M TELLING YOU.
WAIT TILL YOU TRY IT.
LOOK AT THE HOT MOLTEN LAVA
OF SPINACH AND SUCH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GO FOR IT? YEAH.
I SAY GO FOR IT.
IT'S SO HOT.
HOW'S THAT TOMATO, HUH?
OH, THAT'S GOOD. I DO ENJOY
THE ACID FROM THE TOMATO.
AS ODD AS IT SOUNDS,
IT REALLY DOES WORK IN THERE.
AND THE SPINACH IS NICE.
YOU REALLY DO GET
REAL SPINACH OUT OF THAT.
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD
ROCKEFELLER.
IT'S THE BURNT CHEESE AROUND
THE EDGE, IT GETS YA.
IT'S HOT.
THE COMBINATION OF IT ALL--
IT'S NOT JUST SPINACH,
IT'S NOT JUST OYSTERS,
IT'S NOT JUST TOMATO.
COULDN'T GET
ANY BETTER THAN THIS.
EVERYTHING IF FRESH
AND COOKED PERFECTLY.
EVERY SINGLE DAY YOU COME HERE,
YOU'RE GUARANTEED PERFECT FOOD.
TILAPIA,
BLACKENED DOLPHIN, BABY.
CLAMS AND LINGUINI!
THIS IS A CALAMARI SALAD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IS THERE ORANGE CALAMARI
DOWN HERE IN FLORIDA?
THEY MARINATE IT.
I GOTTA PUT A LITTLE
WHALE JUICE ON IT, THOUGH.
WHAT IS WHALE JUICE?
A LITTLE BIT LIKE
A HONEY MUSTARD SAUCE.
IT BRINGS OUT ALL THE FLAVORS.
IT'S AMAZING. I LOVE IT.
THAT'S OUR HOUSE DRESSING,
THE WHALE JUICE--
4 GALLONS OF MAYONNAISE.
THIS MUCH?
THIS IS ONLY
HALF A BATCH.
(whistles) LOOK AT THAT.
SO NOW WE HAVE
4 GALLONS OF MAYO.
WE GOT LOTS
OF MAYONNAISE.
2 OUNCES OF BLACK PEPPER,
WHITE VINEGAR HERE.
I'M DOWN WITH THAT.
ABOUT 3 POUNDS OF SUGAR,
2 CUPS OF MUSTARD,
THEN WE JUST WHIP.
DOES THE WATER GO IN?
I DO THE WATER
AT THE END.
TO JUST GET
THE RIGHT VISCOSITY?
YEP.
SO IS IT GOOD TO GO?
AFTER IT SITS
IN THE FRIDGE OVERNIGHT.
THE SUGAR BREAKS DOWN.
GOOD STUFF, MAN.
IT'S A MUST
WITH THE WHALE FRIES,
BUT IT GOES
WITH ALL THEIR STUFF.
ESPECIALLY THE SANDWICHES.
CHEESE COMBO.
SWISS, AMERICAN,
PROVOLONE. FANTASTIC.
THE WHALE--COLD CUTS, CAPICOLA,
EXTRA WHALE JUICE ON THE SIDE.
DELICIOUS.
WHAT ELSE SHOULD
I TRY WHEN I COME HERE?
GET A FRIED DOLPHIN
KEY WEST.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE.
COLE SLAW,
THOUSAND ISLAND DRESSING
ON A FRIED PIECE
OF DOLPHIN.
IT IS FANTASTIC.
BUT WE'RE NOT
TALKING ABOUT FLIPPER,
WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE FISH.
THE FISH.
AND WHAT ELSE
DO YOU CALL DOLPHIN?
'CAUSE I DON'T
THINK EVERYBODY--
MAHIMAHI, THEY CALL IT
DORADO OUT WEST I BELIEVE.
SO FRESH IT'LL SLAP YA.
OH, YOU BETCHA.
WE'RE GOING TO REMOVE
THE FAT THERE ON THE BELLY MEAT.
DO MY BEST TO CUT
7-OUNCE PORTIONS.
YOU'RE SHY
ON THAT ONE.
YOU SURE?
YEAH. THAT
RIGHT THERE, 7 FLAT.
7 EVEN? THAT'S
PRETTY GOOD, BROTHER.
THAT'S ON THE MONEY.
WE ARE TAKING APPLICATIONS.
OKAY,
SO YOU BUTTERFLY IT,
AND HOW CAN I GET
MY DOLPHIN KEY WEST SANDWICH?
BLACKENED, GRILLED OR FRIED.
I HEAR THE BEER BATTER
IS THE MONEY.
WE CAN DO ONE OF THOSE.
WE USE MILLER LITE.
YOU CAN USE
ANY LAGER YOU'D LIKE.
SODA WATER, BLACK PEPPER,
2 OUNCES LAWRY'S SEASONED SALT,
ALL-PURPOSE
SELF-RISING FLOUR,
TILL YOU GET
THE RIGHT CONSISTENCY,
ALMOST THE CONSISTENCY
OF A PANCAKE BATTER.
THEN YOU REFRIGERATE,
AND THEN IT'S READY TO GO.
AND THIS IS A 50/50 BLEND,
CORN FLOUR...
AND ALL-PURPOSE.
YEP.
GETTING THE FLOUR
ON THE FISH
HELPS THE BEER BATTER
STICK TO THE FISH
THE MOISTURE OF THE FISH,
THE FLOUR STICKS TO IT.
THAT'S IT.
WE HIT IT AGAINST
THE CONTAINER A FEW TIMES,
KNOCK OFF
THE EXCESS BATTER.
AND LET IT FLOAT. WOW,
LOOK AT THAT PUFF UP ALREADY.
ALL THAT CARBONATION
IN THE SODA WATER AND THE BEER.
SO WHILE THAT'S COOKING,
YOU GET IT READY.
SURE.
SMELLS GOOD.
50 WHEAT, 50 WHITE.
IT COMES IN EVERY MORNING, ALSO.
WE GOT
2 OUNCES OF THOUSAND.
(whistles)
GENEROUS PORTION.
SANDWICH IS A LITTLE MESSY.
PURPLE SLAW.
AND THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT YOU GUYS MAKE EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
COUPLE SLICES OF SWISS.
AND DOWN IT GOES.
OFF TO THE PIZZA OVEN.
SLAW GETS HOT, TOO?
YES, SIR.
THAT I HAVE NOT SEEN
IN MY LIFETIME.
WAIT TILL YOU TRY IT, BROTHER.
PIECE OF FRIED FISH.
CRISPY AND SUPER HOT.
THAT'S IT.
MMM, I CAN SMELL
THE BEER BATTER.
THE FISH HAS GOT KILLER CRUNCH--
NICE, SUCCULENT, FRESH.
THE WARM SLAW, ACTUALLY,
REALLY BECOMES CREAMY.
I GUESS YOU GOTTA
COME TO FLORIDA
TO GET A SANDWICH
LIKE THAT.
YES, YOU DO.
LIGHT, FLAKY,
THEY'RE TASTY.
VERY FRESH-TASTING.
(man)
BLACKENED DOLPHIN, BABY.
THIS IS THE BEST
OF DEERFIELD.
THE MAIN REASON I CAME TO
FLORIDA WAS TO HAVE THE SEAFOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND I WOULDN'T
REALLY GO ANYWHERE ELSE.
PEOPLE WHO LIVE
AROUND HERE HANG OUT.
THEY KEPT US GOING,
AND FOR A TINY LITTLE PLACE,
I THINK IT'S FANTASTIC.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS.
NEXT STOP, BOISE...
IT'S COLORFUL AND CRAZY,
AND WE LIKE IT.
TO PILE IT ON.
JALAPEÑO, BACON--
I NEED SOME AVOCADO--
CHEDDAR CHEESE AND ONE PIECE
OF JALA JACK. PERFECT.
SO HERE I AM
IN BOISE, IDAHO.
NOW WHEN YOU CRUISE UP
TO A JOINT
THAT IS CALLED DONNIE MAC'S
TRAILER PARK CUISINE,
AND YOU SEE
THE WHOLE FRONT OF THE JOINT
IS COVERED
IN GLASS GARAGE ROLL-UP DOORS,
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
THINGS ARE STARTING
TO LOOK GOOD SO FAR.
SINGLE WIDE.
(man) THANK YOU, SIR.
I LOVE THE FOOD HERE.
THE MESQUITE FLAVOR
OF THE HAMBURGER, SO GOOD.
I GOT A CHILI BAD DOG.
THE CHILI MAC.
IT'S CLASSIC.
WHERE ELSE CAN YOU GO
AND GET SpaghettiOs IN A CAN?
WHICH IS ODD.
EXACTLY.
IT'S A UNIQUE PLACE.
WHAT WAS THIS
PLACE ORIGINALLY?
IT WAS
A GOODYEAR TIRE STORE.
TILL FORMER RESTAURANT OWNER
DONNIE MacKENZIE...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
DECIDED TO GET BACK
IN THE GAME.
I WANTED TO TAKE
BASIC AMERICAN FOOD
AND BE AS CREATIVE
AS YOU WANT WITH IT.
KIDS MINI WIDE.
SO HE BROUGHT
IN CHEF DEREK FERNANDES...
AMBER, PLEASE.
TO DO AMERICAN ROAD FOOD
WITH A TWIST.
JUNKYARD DOG.
CHILI BAD DOG.
THE JALAPEÑOS ARE PRETTY SPICY,
HAVE SOME BITE TO THEM.
CLAM CHOWDER THAT HAS
ZUCCHINI AND CARROTS IN IT.
THE NASTY NACHOS--
MESSY BUT TOTALLY WORTH IT.
AND THEIR TAKE
ON A FRIED CHICKEN SANDWICH.
SOUTHERN FRIED CHICKEN.
TOPPED WITH
A HAND-CUT SLAW
JUST LIKE DONNIE MAC'S
MOM USED TO MAKE.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
WE START WITH
ROASTED CORN DRESSING
THAT GOES WITH CABBAGE
TO CREATE A SLAW.
I LIKE IT, I LIKE IT.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
THAT CORN RIGHT IN THERE.
SO WE'RE NOT ROASTING
THE CORN ON THE GRILL
ACTUALLY MORE
OF A SAUTé METHOD.
OKAY.
THROW SOME GARLIC IN THERE.
PUT A LITTLE MORE IN.
I CAN REALLY
SMELL THAT CORN.
ONCE THIS IS CARAMELIZED,
THROW IT STRAIGHT
INTO THE ROBOT COUPE.
JUST FOR A FEW SECONDS--
YOU DON'T WANT TO DECIMATE IT.
ADD SOME BUTTERMILK,
SLOWLY POUR THAT IN.
RANCH DRESSING, A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
GIVE THAT A TASTE.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
SCALLIONS IN RIGHT AT THE END.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
DRESSING'S MADE,
SLAW'S READY.
NOW IT'S TIME
FOR THE FRIED CHICKEN.
YEP. PANKO.
MY FAVORITE.
GONNA PUT A LITTLE FLOUR IN,
TOO, HELP IT BIND. GARLIC.
WOW.
LET'S DO SOME SALT,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
2 TABLESPOONS TO 5.
WHO'S COUNTING?
EXACTLY. THYME.
THYME LOVES CHICKEN.
A LITTLE BIT OF PAPRIKA.
OKAY.
NOW THIS
IS THE FUN PART.
YOU GOTTA GET OUT
MORE OFTEN THEN.
HERE'S OUR CHICKEN,
AND IT'S BEEN MARINATING
IN BUTTERMILK OVERNIGHT.
KINDA HOW
I DO MINE, OKAY.
PRESS SOME ON TOP.
YOU KINDA WANT
TO LET IT SIT FOR A MINUTE.
YOU WANT TO LET THE BREADCRUMBS
KINDA SOAK INTO THE BUTTERMILK
THAT'S ON THE CHICKEN.
EXACTLY.
WHILE THAT'S SITTING THERE,
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GET A CIABATTA BUN
ON THE GRILL.
NOW WE'RE READY TO GO AHEAD
AND START FRYING OUR CHICKEN.
DROP IT RIGHT IN.
I LIKE IT, BUDDY.
WE'RE GONNA COME
OVER HERE WITH THE BUN,
MAKE SURE WE GET A LITTLE
OF THIS SAUCE ON THE BOTTOM.
SO CABBAGE DOESN'T ABSORB
IT ALL UP. NICE CIABATTAS.
PRETTY GENEROUS AMOUNT OF THIS
ON HERE. JUST GONNA MIX IT UP.
AND YOU'LL DO THIS
TO ORDER EACH TIME?
ABSOLUTELY.
THE LAST THING YOU WANT IS
WILTED SLAW ON YOUR SANDWICH.
SOGGY SLAW, RIGHT.
NO GOOD. YOU'RE GONNA
GET THE CHICKEN BREAST.
TAKE A NICE
HEAPING HANDFUL.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
LID IT JUST LIKE THAT.
LID IT.
MMM, THAT'S
A GREAT BALANCE.
SWEETNESS OF THE CORN,
THE BITTERNESS OF THE CABBAGE,
THE CRUNCH OF THE CHICKEN,
THE SOFT OF THE ROLL.
THAT'S DONE
THE RIGHT WAY. MMM.
I LOVE THAT. THAT WAS
A GOOD SANDWICH, MAN.
YEAH? GOOD,
GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
REALLY GOOD.
IT'S REALLY CRUNCHY.
I LIKE THAT.
EVERYTHING IS REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
WE LOVE THE FOOD
AND THE ENVIRONMENT.
IT'S SUCH
A UNIQUE PLACE.
ORDER.
WHERE ORDERS COME IN
ON A ZIP LINE.
JUST IN.
AND YOU COULD
EAT IN THE CAR.
MMM.
THEIRS, NOT YOURS.
THIS IS MY FIRST TIME.
IT'S VERY POPULAR.
SO THIS IS OUR
SPECIAL TIME RIGHT NOW.
YEAH.
IT'S GOT
KIND OF A JUNKYARD FEEL.
THE CRUSHED TRUCKS
FOR COFFEE TABLES,
THE TAILGATES
FOR THE COUNTERTOP.
IT'S COLORFUL AND CRAZY,
AND WE LIKE IT.
IT'S JUST
A FUN PLACE TO EAT.
THERE YOU GO.
AND THE FAVORITES HERE,
THE DONNIE MAC BURGERS.
SINGLE WIDE
WITH CHEDDAR CHEESE.
THE DOUBLE WIDE BURGER.
WE COOK IT
ON THE MESQUITE GRILL.
FANTASTIC.
THE FLAVOR IS THERE
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
KIND OF JUST REMINDS ME
OF A BARBECUE.
WHOA. (whistles)
IN WE GO.
WHAT, ARE WE LOADING
THE STEAM ENGINE, HOSS?
(chugs like train)
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE BUILD YOUR OWN BURGER.
WHAT CAN I PUT ON IT?
JUST ABOUT
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
LET'S TAKE
A LOOK RIGHT HERE.
SOME JALAPEÑO,
CHEDDAR CHEESE,
BACON, RED BELL PEPPER.
PERFECT. GO AHEAD
AND PATTY UP THE BURGER HERE.
80/20 GROUND BEEF.
YEP. JUST SMASH IT DOWN.
BETWEEN THE TWO PLATES. AND YOU
HAND-PRESS THESE EVERY MORNING?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I LIKE IT. I LIKE THE UNIFORM
NOT ROUND-CIRCLE-LIKE.
SALT AND PEPPER,
ANYTHING ON IT?
ABSOLUTELY. WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON A CIABATTA BUN.
A LITTLE BUTTER, GET OUR
BACON GOIN', JALAPEÑOS ON.
JALAPEÑO, RED BELL PEPPER.
NICE-LOOKIN' OF BACON.
A LITTLE APPLE WOOD SMOKED
BACON, THEN FLIP IT OVER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
HIT THE CHEESE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ONE PIECE OF CHEDDAR
AND ONE PIECE OF JALA JACK.
I MEAN, I'M
IN THE TRAILER PARK.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND PULL THIS CIABATTA BUN.
THIS IS OUR TRAILER SAUCE--
MAYONNAISE, SOME RELISH,
KETCHUP, MUSTARD,
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET THESE
JALAPEÑOS AND PEPPERS ON THERE.
IT MUST BE A LITTLE DANCE
HE'S GOT GOING HERE.
A COUPLE
OF STRIPS OF BACON.
I NEED SOME AVOCADO, TOO.
PERFECT. WHAT SIZE DID I GET?
THIS IS OUR SINGLE WIDE.
THIS IS 1/3 OF A POUND PATTY.
BIGGEST BURGER YOU CAN GET
IS OUR DOUBLE WIDE.
IT'S A 1/2 POUND
OF BEEF.
YOU ONLY
GAVE ME ONE PATTY.
YOU DON'T THINK
I CAN HANDLE A BIG...
WELL, WE'LL SEE.
IT'S PRETTY FILLING.
MMM, I LIKE IT, MAN.
WITH THE JALAPEÑOS
AND ROASTED PEPPERS--
GOOD BURGER COOKED
THE RIGHT WAY.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT'S JUICY.
SUPER GOOD. IT JUST HAS
THAT SMOKY FLAVOR.
WHAT DO THE KIDS
ENJOY HAVING?
THEY LOVE
THE MAC AND CHEESE.
AND YOU CAN GET IT
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
MAC AND CHEESE,
ADD HOT DOG.
I'M MAKING MY CHOICE...
EXCELLENT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WHO WANTS
A BITE OF THAT?
ORDER IN!
AT DONNIE MAC'S TRAILER PARK
CUISINE IN BOISE...
JUST IN,
TWO SOUTHERN FRIES!
YOU GUYS ENJOY YOUR MEAL,
YOUR LUNCH?
DONNIE MacKENZIE'S
DOING ROAD FOOD WITH A TWIST...
JUNKYARD DOG.
FROM HOT DOGS
TO LOADED BURGERS.
PEPPERS AND JALAPEÑOS.
AND HOMEMADE
MAC AND CHEESE.
REALLY, REALLY,
REALLY CHEESY.
BETTER THAN HOMEMADE.
MMM. NOT LACKIN' ON
THE CHEESE IN THAT, BROTHER.
AND THEY'LL TOP IT
WITH JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
ONE MAC AND CHEESE,
ADD CHILI.
MAC AND CHEESE
WITH HOT DOGS.
WITH THIS, JUST LIKE
WITH A BURGER,
YOU CAN GET IT
HOWEVER YOU WANT IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
EVERYTHING YOU HAVE.
WE ARE GONNA
COOK EVERYTHING YOU HAVE,
AND WE ARE GONNA
MAKE THE THUNDER PLATTER.
WE CAN DO THAT.
CAN YOU FEEL IT?
YEAH, OH, YEAH.
I THINK WE NEED TO START OFF
WITH SOME ONION RINGS.
WE JUST SOAK THEM
IN BUTTERMILK OVERNIGHT,
DROP THEM RIGHT IN LIKE THAT.
GET SOME SWEET POTATO
FRIES DOWN.
OKAY, NOW WE GOTTA
GET WORKING ON THE FLAT TOP.
I'M THINKING
HOT DOG, BACON.
I THINK SOME RED ONIONS,
GREEN BELL PEPPER,
JALAPEÑOS, OLIVES,
OH, SOME ANAHEIM CHILIES.
SEE THE WAY
IT'S COMING TOGETHER?
CAN YOU FEEL THE MAGIC?
MAYBE A BURGER PATTY
ON TOP.
I GOT ONE MORE TRICK
UP MY SLEEVE.
WE GOT BACON
MIXED INTO THAT,
BUT I THINK WE NEED TO GET
A LITTLE FUNKY WITH THIS.
LIKE A LITTLE
BACON BLANKET.
THIS IS A NEW ONE.
SERVE THIS UP WITH A REALLY NICE
ROLAIDS CREAM SAUCE ON TOP.
ANY OTHER INGREDIENTS
I HAVE NOT SEEN?
WHAT ABOUT THE CHEESE
ON THE BURGER?
WE COULD HEAT UP
SOME OF THE CHEESE SAUCE
AND POUR THAT
OVER THE DICED BURGER.
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL.
LET'S GET STAT
ON SOME MAC AND CHEESE
'CAUSE WE'RE READY
TO ASSEMBLE.
ALL RIGHT.
THUNDER PLATE.
SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
GO. THIS IS GONNA BE AWESOME.
OKAY, BRING ALL THE WARRIORS IN.
OH, I THINK
A TORTILLA CHIP BASE.
OKAY. I THINK
WE SHOULD START WITH THE MAC.
WONDERFULLY DONE.
THEN PATTY...
YEAH.
AND A LITTLE
CHEESE SAUCE.
SOUNDS GREAT.
EXCELLENT.
THE SWEET POTATO FRIES.
GONNA ADD
SOME NICE COLOR.
IT DOES.
I THINK
WE GO WITH THIS.
SOME OF--SOME OF THAT.
FANTASTIC.
DROP IN SOME BIG RINGS AROUND
THE TOP. MORE CHEESE SAUCE?
SURE.
YEAH.
YOU CAN ALWAYS
USE MORE CHEESE SAUCE.
ALWAYS MORE CHEESE SAUCE.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL GARNISH.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE ARE COMPLAINING
THESE DAYS ABOUT EDIBLE GARNISH.
TO ME, THAT SAYS EDIBLE. WHERE
ARE YOU AT WITH THIS, COWBOY?
STILL GOT
A HOT DOG LEFT.
OHH, WE DO. I LIKE WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING THERE.
MORE CHEESE SAUCE?
OH, NICE MOVE.
READY FOR THE SECRET?
UH-OH.
LITTLE BIT OF CHEETO
RIGHT UP ON THE TOP OF THAT.
RIGHT THERE, NOW THAT'S
MAC AND CHEESE GONE WILD, HUH?
I GOT MAC AND CHEESE,
ONION, ONION RING,
SWEET POTATO,
I GOT THE BACON.
I TOP IT OFF WITH
A LITTLE CHEETO.
THAT RIGHT THERE,
THAT'S A CHAMPIONSHIP BITE.
SPREADIN' IT AROUND.
MM-HMM.
CHEETOS MAKE IT.
(laughing)
I'M NOT KIDDING YA.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU
A LITTLE TREAT, FRIEND.
NEXT DINNER PARTY YOU HAVE,
GIVE THEM ONE
OF THOSE BACON CROSTINIS.
MMM.
GOOD EATS? WELCOME
TO THE TRAILER PARK!
I JUST LIKE COMING HERE
'CAUSE THERE'S LOTS OF DIFFERENT
THINGS TO EAT.
SINGLE WIDE, AMERICAN CHEESE,
REGULAR FRIES.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
YEAH, TRAILER PARK CUISINE--
I'LL HAVE THAT.
CUP OF KILLER CHILI.
WE CAME IN.
IT WAS FABULOUS.
ORDER UP!
I THINK IT'S A LOT OF FUN.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
NEXT TIME YOU COME,
I JUST WANT YOU TO ORDER
THUNDER PLATE.
SO IS THAT
A MONEY ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
READY? IT'S COMING IN
FAST AND HOT.
MMM, AAH!
WOW!
I'M LUCKY MY WATCH
DIDN'T GO IN THERE!