HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHO WAS THE ONE
THAT E-MAILED ME?
(cheering)
YOU PICKED IT.
IN OKARCHE, OKLAHOMA...
COMIN' AT YA.
A FAMILY JOINT...
HERE WE GO.
SERVING 5 TONS OF CHICKEN
A WEEK...
THE BEST CHICKEN
I'VE EVER HAD.
DONE THE SAME WAY...
BE CAREFUL, IT'S HOT.
FOR 49 YEARS.
MMM.
EXCELLENT, MAN.
IN LOS ANGELES,
HOMEMADE, MOIST--
IT'S AWESOME.
THE TAMALE JOINT...
TAMALE COMBO.
WHERE THEY'RE STUFFIN' THEM
ALL KINDS OF WAYS.
CHICKEN MOLE
IS JUST THE BEST.
HOT PINEAPPLE--A LITTLE BIT
LIKE HAVING A DESSERT.
SPINACH AND CHEESE.
MMM, THE MASA'S OUTSTANDING.
YEAH?
AND IN HOUSTON...
I THOUGHT NEW YORK
WAS GOOD.
WHERE A NEW YORK
DELI DUDE...
MA'AM, YOU SEE THAT?
LIKE A PICTURE.
IS KEEPING
TRADITION ALIVE.
THIS IS MY CALLING,
TO ELEVATE EASTERN EUROPEAN
JEWISH FOOD.
AND, HEY,
HOW ABOUT A SANDWICH?
THIS IS CALLED
THE ZELLAGABETSKY.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, WHEN I THINK
SMALL TOWN MIDDLE AMERICA,
I THINK FARMING AND FAMILIES,
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE COMING
INTO TOWN TO GET THEIR SUPPLIES.
BUT HOW ABOUT A PLACE
THAT'S BEEN OPEN FOR BUSINESS
MORE THAN 110 YEARS
AND SERVES--NOW GET THIS--
OVER 24,000 PIECES
OF FRIED CHICKEN A WEEK?
THAT'S RIGHT, 24,000 PIECES
OF FRIED CHICKEN A WEEK.
I HEARD THIS, AND I HAD
TO COME CHECK OUT EISCHEN'S
HERE IN OKARCHE, OKLAHOMA.
WHO WAS THE ONE
THAT E-MAILED ME,
SAID I HAD TO COME
CHECK THIS JOINT OUT?
(cheering)
I LOVE FRIED CHICKEN.
COMIN' AT YA.
IT'S ABOUT THE CHICKEN.
IT IS.
ALWAYS HOT AND FRESH.
DID YOU E-MAIL ME?
I DID. I E-MAILED YOU
IN FEBRUARY.
WHY DID YOU
SEND THIS TO ME?
IT'S GOT A LOT
OF HISTORY BEHIND IT.
KNOWN AS ONE OF THE OLDEST BARS
IN OKLAHOMA
AND BEST FRIED CHICKEN
IN THE STATE.
JUST ASK ANYONE HERE.
HOW'S THE FRIED CHICKEN?
(cheering)
HERE WE GO.
CHICKEN STARTED IN 1960.
MY BROTHER GEORGE--
HE WOULD COOK ON ONE
OF THE OLD CAST IRON SKILLETS
ON A STOVE.
OH!
GEORGE PASSED AWAY
BACK IN 1964,
BUT HIS BROTHERS ED...
LOOKIN' GOOD.
AND PAUL...
DOIN' FINE.
ARE STILL SERVING IT
THE ONLY WAY YOU CAN GET IT...
BE CAREFUL, IT'S HOT.
THE WAY WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IT.
DON'T CHANGE A THING.
ONE WHOLE CUT-UP BIRD
AT A TIME.
LOADIN' 'EM UP.
ONLY NOW IT TAKES
EIGHT ELECTRIC FRYERS
JUST TO KEEP UP.
ALL RIGHT.
HOW DO WE COMMENCE
THE "CHICKEN-ATION"?
FIRST OF ALL,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A BREADING.
WHEAT FLOUR.
AND WHY WHEAT FLOUR?
THAT'S WHAT MY BROTHER
STARTED WHEN--
OKAY.
SO A LOT OF THIS
GOES TO DO WITH YOUR BROTHER.
MY BROTHER,
HE MADE THE RECIPE.
AND THEN WE ADD
SOME CORNMEAL, SOME SALT,
A LITTLE BIT
OF BAKING POWDER.
NOW WE'RE NOT MARINATING
THIS CHICKEN OR ANYTHING?
NO. A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR,
PAPRIKA...
(whistles)
AND A COUPLE OTHER SPICES
THAT I'M NOT TELLING ANYBODY.
CAN I TASTE IT?
TAKES LIKE PAPRIKA...
YEAH.
AND WITH SOME OTHER STUFF.
OH, YEAH, IT'S DEFINITELY
GOT SOME OTHER STUFF...
OKAY.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
OUT OF RESPECT
FOR WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE
AND HOW LONG
THIS HAS BEEN GOING ON,
I AIN'T GONNA SAY IT.
OKAY. NOW WE GOTTA
MIX IT ALL UP.
YOU'RE THE FIRST PERSON
OTHER THAN FAMILY
IN 40-SOME YEARS
THAT HAS SEEN ANYBODY MIX THIS.
ARE YOU READY TO DUST
SOME CHICKEN? OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
THE WHOLE CHICKEN
AT A TIME.
SO EVEN ON YOUR BIRTHDAY,
YOU CAN'T COME IN
AND JUST GET ALL WINGS?
NO, NO, NO.
OH.
THAT'S THE WAY IT ALWAYS WAS.
THAT'S THE WAY IT'S GONNA BE.
'CAUSE THAT'S WHAT
YOUR BROTHER DID.
OH, YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
HE DID,
AND WE'RE NOT CHANGING
ANY OF THAT.
CAN DIG THAT.
DO YOU HAVE A FAVORITE FRYER?
DO YOU NAME THEM?
THIS IS A GOOD
ONE HERE--ELSIE.
YOU NAMED IT ELSIE?
WANDA, WHEEZY,
PENELOPE AND SANDY.
ABOUT WHAT TEMPERATURE
YOU RUNNIN' THESE--350?
330.
330?
YEAH.
SO IT DOESN'T COOK IT AS FAST
AND GET IT AS BROWN AS FAST.
IT MAKES SURE THAT YOU COOK
THAT MEAT ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
YEAH.
AND HOW MANY MINUTES DOES IT
TAKE TO COOK A CHICKEN?
15 MINUTES.
I THOUGHT THAT THE WINGS
COOKED A LITTLE FASTER
THAN THE BREASTS.
THAT'S THE WAY
WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IT.
THAT'S JUST THE WAY
WE DO IT.
SO HOW ABOUT THIS--NEW RULE--
QUIT ASKING QUESTIONS.
GIVE THAT A LITTLE BIT
OF A STIR.
SO THEY DON'T STICK TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S IT.
SEE, I WANT THIS. YOU JUST
CALL IT CHICKEN, HUH?
WHAT DO YOU LIKE THE BEST?
I'LL PUT THEM ON TOP.
OH, I'M A WING
AND THIGH KINDA GUY.
THIGH. THIGH.
WELL, THIS
IS JUST RIDICULOUS,
'CAUSE IT'S MOLTEN HOT
RIGHT NOW.
MM-HMM. I KNOW.
(laughs)
MMM. EXCELLENT, MAN.
SUPER TENDER AND JUICY.
THE SKIN
TURNS INTO A NICE CRUST,
BECAUSE OF THE FLOUR
AND THE CORNMEAL.
BUT, BOY, IT'S GOOD.
IT'S COOLED DOWN TO A POINT NOW
WHERE I CAN JUST START
SHOVELING IT IN.
(woman)
HERE'S YOUR CHICKEN.
THE MOST TENDER, THE JUICIEST
CHICKEN I'VE EVER HAD.
TASTES LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER'S CHICKEN.
IT'S CRISPY.
IT'S CRUNCHY.
I KINDA LIKE TO MIX IN
THE BREAD AND BUTTER PICKLE.
AND AROUND HERE,
EVERYBODY'S GOT THEIR OWN WAY
OF EATING IT.
PICK AT IT AND PICK AT IT,
AND THEN YOU GO AT IT.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE
A BITE OF YOUR CHICKEN
AND A BITE OF THE PICKLE
AND A BITE OF ONIONS.
PICKLE, ONION... MMM.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT
RIGHT THERE.
101'S READY.
THEY MAKE OTHER THINGS
AT THIS RESTAURANT, CORRECT?
I DON'T KNOW.
NO?
I'VE NEVER ORDERED
ANYTHING BUT THE...
I'VE SEEN BIGGER MENUS
AT A BALL GAME.
THE ROAST BEEF
IS VERY GOOD.
FRIED OKRA IS PERFECT.
HOW ARE THE SALADS?
WHAT?
(man) DO THEY HAVE
SALAD HERE?
(woman) FRITO CHILI PIE--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
ALWAYS HOT,
MELTS THE CHEESE.
HE MAKES
THE HOMEMADE CHILI.
OKAY. WELL, WE GOTTA MAKE
SOME OF THAT.
SAME WAY
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN MADE,
AND THAT'S GEORGE'S RECIPE,
TOO.
FIRST OF ALL, I HAVE TO PUT IN
HALF A GALLON OF SALTED WATER.
I DON'T SEE ANY SEASONING.
OH, NOT YET.
OH.
THEN WE ADD
APPROXIMATELY 10 POUNDS
OF GROUND BEEF TO THAT.
THEN I MIX IT
IN THE WATER.
THEN I'LL ADD THE REST
OF THE GROUND BEEF TO IT.
SO YOU JUST MUSH THAT UP
ON THE BOTTOM...
MM-HMM.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA PUT
THE LOGS OF FUN UP TOP?
ON TOP.
AND HOW MANY POUNDS
IS THIS HERE?
40 POUNDS. THEN I'LL MUSH
THEM A LITTLE.
MUSH IT UP A LITTLE MORE.
IS THAT "MUSH"?
MUSH. (laughs) NOW WE'RE READY
TO JUST COVER IT UP WITH FOIL.
WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THE SPOON, BOSS?
GOTTA STIR THE CHILI.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA LEAVE
THE SPOON IN THERE?
WHILE IT'S COOKING, YES.
WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S ALWAYS
BEEN DONE LIKE THAT.
(laughs)
SO THE RULE IS YOU'RE GONNA
LEAVE THE SPOON IN THE MEAT...
IN THE MEAT.
ON TOP OF THE STOVE.
STOVE, UH-HUH. MM-HMM.
WHO TAUGHT YOU THIS?
THAT'S THE WAY
WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IT.
WHEN DOES THE FLAVOR
COME TO IT?
WHEN I'M ABOUT DONE COOKING,
I PUT ALL THE SEASONING IN IT.
WE'RE GONNA GO PUT THIS
ON TOP OF THE STOVE?
YES.
OH, AWESOME.
COOK LOW
FOR SIX OR SEVEN HOURS.
MEAT A LA SPOON IS DONE?
MM-HMM.
OKAY.
LOOKS GOOD.
ADDING OUR MINCED ONIONS.
DRIED MINCED ONIONS.
YES. UH-HUH.
NOW WE'RE ADDING OUR SALT,
AND I LIKE TO STIR THAT
IN THE MEAN A LITTLE BIT.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
YEAH, I LIKE THAT.
A LITTLE COMINO.
BLACK PEPPER, PAPRIKA.
AND SOME CHILI POWDER.
WE'RE GONNA WORK THAT
INTO THE MEAT.
SO THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
ADDING 2 15-OUNCE CANS
OF BEANS
AND 2 15-OUNCE CANS
OF TOMATO SAUCE.
NOW WE'LL ADD THE MEAT.
YOU JUST SCOOP
THE MEAT UP IN THERE.
HOW MANY OF THIS SPOON
RIGHT HERE DO YOU HAVE?
HOW MANY DIFFERENT?
THIS ONE.
YOU HAVE ONE SPOON?
ONE SPOON.
ONE COOKING SPOON, HUH?
WE DON'T NEED A SPOON
FOR THE CHICKEN.
NO. NO.
ONLY FOR THE CHILI,
AND THEY'RE GOING THROUGH
100 POUNDS A WEEK
BY ITSELF...
THERE IT IS.
IN FRITO PIE...
MMM.
JUST GOOD OLD CHILI...
MM-HMM.
FRITOS.
I LIKE IT, MAN.
AND THIS HEAVY-HITTER.
CHILI-CHEESE NACHOS.
CAN I TRY ONE?
ABSOLUTELY.
MMM. THEY'RE GOOD.
OLD STYLE. MMM. WONDERFUL.
A GREAT PLACE TO EAT.
EVERYONE JUST LOVES IT.
I THOUGHT MY MOTHER'S CHICKEN
WAS THE BEST,
BUT THIS IS THE BEST CHICKEN
I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S JUST GOOD CHICKEN.
HOW OFTEN DO YOU GUYS
COME HERE?
AS OFTEN AS WE CAN
DRIVE IN FROM NORMAN.
HOW FAR IS THAT
FROM HERE?
A GOOD HOUR.
SERIOUSLY--YOU GUYS DRIVE
AN HOUR TO GO HERE?
ABSOLUTELY.
WELL, THANK YOU
FOR THE E-MAIL.
I APPRECIATE IT
AND JUST SO YOU KNOW...
NO PROBLEM.
I LOVE YOUR SHOW.
EVERYBODY JUST GET
A REAL CLOSE LOOK AT HER.
THIS THE ONE YOU BLAME
WHEN EVERYBODY COMES HERE.
1,200 PEOPLE. 900,000 E-MAILS.
THAT Y'ALL VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT. WOW.
(cheering)
UP NEXT...
SPINACH AND CHEESE TAMALE.
WE'RE HEADING WEST...
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
IT'S SO PERFECTLY MADE.
FOR MOM'S TAMALES.
IT ALL CAME FROM SEEING
MY MOM IN THE KITCHEN.
SPINACH AND CHEESE, THAT'S
CRAZY. I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER--
MMM. I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER SEEN IT.
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY
TO THE STADIUM FOR THE BIG GAME.
NOW MOST PEOPLE HAVE THAT JOINT
THEY JUST GOTTA STOP
AND VISIT,
YOU KNOW, TO GET
THAT GREAT SLICE OF PIZZA
OR MAYBE
THAT REALLY UNIQUE SANDWICH.
BUT LET'S SAY
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY
TO DODGERS STADIUM
IN LOS ANGELES,
AND YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR SOME REALLY KILLER TAMALES.
I HEAR THE PLACE YOU GOTTA HIT
IS RIGHT HERE--MOM'S TAMALES.
YOUR CORN AND CHEESE TAMALE.
THE TAMALES--
THERE'S NO COMPARISON.
HOMEMADE, MOIST--
IT'S AWESOME.
TAMALE COMBO READY.
THIS IS MY TAMALE FIX.
REALLY? THAT GOOD?
SO GOOD, SHE E-MAILED ME
AND SAID, "HEY, CHECK IT OUT."
WHAT DO YOU THINK
MAKES THIS ONE SO GOOD?
IT'S REALLY HOMEMADE,
AND I REALLY LOVE TAMALES.
THE CHICKEN MOLE
IS JUST THE BEST.
BEEF TAMALES--
THEY ARE DELICIOUS.
YOU COMPARE THE TAMALES
TO THE ONES
THAT YOUR GRANDMAS MADE.
OR KARLA RODRIGUEZ MOM'S
HAS MADE.
(speaking Spanish)
IT ALL CAME FROM SEEING
MY MOM IN THE KITCHEN.
(speaking Spanish)
I LIKE COOKING.
I TOOK IT ON.
AND FOUR YEARS AGO,
SHE TOOK ON HER OWN RESTAURANT
WITH HER MOM
AT HER SIDE...
(speaking Spanish)
WHAT BETTER
THAN WORK WITH FAMILY?
USING FAMILY RECIPES
FOR TAMALES DONE
EIGHT DIFFERENT WAYS.
TAMALE COMBO.
FROM CHICKEN...
THERE'S NO COMPARISON.
TO PINEAPPLE.
HOT PINEAPPLE--
KIND OF A SURPRISE.
AND THIS FAMILY FAVORITE--
SPINACH AND CHEESE.
JUST MOUTHWATERING.
TO DIE FOR.
SERIOUSLY?
OKAY, SO...
SO WE THROW SOME OIL
INTO OUR PAN HERE.
TOMATOES, ONIONS,
JALAPEÑOS.
AND WE'LL SAUTé THIS.
GARLIC POWDER.
CHICKEN BROTH POWDER
AND CHICKEN BROTH.
YOU LET THIS SIT HERE
AND JUST KINDA STEW DOWN?
YEAH.
AND THEN THAT WILL GO
IN THE TAMALE?
YEAH.
LOOKS GREAT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
NOW WHAT'S GOIN' ON
WITH THE MASA HERE?
OUR MASA'S MADE
ESPECIALLY FOR US,
ABOUT 100 POUNDS A DAY.
THEY TOOK THE DRY MASA,
AND THEY INCORPORATE
THE VEGETABLE SHORTENING,
AND YOU'RE GOING TO TAKE IT
TO ANOTHER LEVEL
BY ADDING
THE CHICKEN STOCK.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO THROW IT ALL IN.
WE KIND OF MIX IT AND--
LOOKING FOR THE TEXTURE.
YEAH.
DO YOU TAKE YOUR BLING OFF?
IT IS NICE AND LIGHT
AND CREAMY.
WE KNOW IT'S DONE,
'CAUSE IT KINDA JUST
FALLS RIGHT OFF.
THAT'S THE CONSISTENCY
RIGHT THERE. OKAY.
THAT'S THE ONE.
WE HAVE THE CORN HUSKS
THAT HAVE BEEN SOAKED
IN WATER.
YEAH. THIS IS THE MASA.
SPINACH THERE.
SOME OF THAT.
THE TOMATO AND JALAPEÑO
MIXTURE THAT WE MADE.
MONTEREY JACK CHEESE.
FOLD IT UP.
WRAP IT UP.
AH, SEE, IT'S SO NICE
HAVING THE TIN FOIL.
THIS IS SET IT
AND FORGET IT.
YEAH.
WHAT WE'RE DOING
IS WE'RE COOKING THE MASA
AND FLAVORING THE MASA WITH
THE INGREDIENTS THAT ARE INSIDE.
THAT IS RIGHT.
SO HOW LONG
HAVE THESE BEEN ON?
40 MINUTES.
SEE HOW WE DID.
SO THIS IS THE EVER-SO-FAMOUS
SPINACH AND CHEESE.
MMM,
THE MASA'S OUTSTANDING.
YEAH?
IT HOLDS TOGETHER
REAL NICE.
BUT SPINACH AND CHEESE,
THAT'S CRAZY.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER--
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN IT.
I DEFINITELY THINK
THERE'S MORE MOISTURE
AND MORE OF THE FLAVOR
INVOLVED IN IT.
IS KEPT IN IT.
YEAH.
MMM. REALLY GOOD.
REALLY GOOD TAMALE.
SPINACH AND CHEESE TAMALE.
IT'S MY FAVORITE. THESE ARE
JUST, LIKE, SO PERFECTLY MADE.
HANDS DOWN, THE SPINACH
TAMALE'S THE WAY TO GO.
YEAH.
THAT MASA TO FILLING RATIO
IS WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT.
IT IS.
IT'S PERFECT.
THESE ARE GOOD TAMALES.
SO GOOD
THAT KARLA'S NOW CRANKING OUT
MORE THAN 1,500 A WEEK...
TAMALE COMBO.
NINE YEARS
AFTER STARTING THE WHOLE BIZ
OUT OF THE BACK OF HER CAR.
ANYWHERE THERE WERE
CONSTRUCTION WORKERS GOING
WHO WERE HUNGRY,
WE WERE THERE.
AND SINCE SHE'S OPENED
THIS JOINT...
HERE'S YOUR SOPES ASADAS.
KARLA'S BEEN ABLE TO ADD
ALL KINDS OF FAMILY RECIPES...
TWO CHILE RELLENO COMBOS.
PASSED DOWN FROM GRANDMA
TO MOM TO HER.
THANK YOU.
WE'VE HAD EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU.
CHICKEN ENCHILADAS.
I EAT THEM
EVERY WEEKEND.
EVERY WEEKEND?
EVERY WEEKEND FOR
THE LAST THREE YEARS. MMM.
CARNE ASADA TACOS
ARE EXCELLENT.
AND CHILE RELLENOS
DONE GRANDMA'S WAY...
(Karla) READY.
NOT DEEP-FRIED--
PAN-FRIED.
WHAT IS THIS WE'RE MAKING?
THE CHILE RELLENO SAUCE.
WE COOK DOWN ROMA TOMATOES.
WAS THERE ANY SALT
IN THE WATER?
NO, NO, NO. NO SALT.
AND WE'RE DOING SKIN,
SEEDS, EVERYTHING?
EVERYTHING.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'LL BE USING
THAT WATER AS WELL.
AND A LITTLE
CHICKEN BASE?
YES. GARLIC HERE.
DO YOU EVER WONDER HOW
THEY DRIED UP THE CHICKEN
AND GOT IT INTO THAT POWDER?
NO, I DON'T.
WE'RE GONNA
SAUTé OUR SAUCE NOW.
SO THIS HAS BEEN PREHEATED.
VEGETABLE OIL AND FLOUR.
SPRINKLE IT IN?
YEAH.
STIR THAT.
MAKING A ROUX?
TO GIVE IT THAT
THICKENING.
WE ADD THE BLENDED TOMATO.
AAH!
WEARIN' A LIME GREEN SHIRT,
AND IT'S A SPLATTER FEST.
A LITTLE MEXICAN OREGANO.
YES.
AND THIS IS ALL JUST A SAUCE
FOR THE CHILE RELLENO?
YES.
SO THIS IS READY TO GO. WE LET
THIS SIMMER A LITTLE BIT MORE,
AND THEN WE'LL START WORKING
ON THE CHILE RELLENO.
SO WE GOT OUR BATTER HERE.
NOW OUR BATTER'S--
WHAT DO WE HAVE IN HERE?
EGG WHITES--
YOU BEAT THOSE.
SO YOU GET THE EGG WHITES
BROUGHT UP FIRST.
YEAH, THEN THE FLOUR.
THEN YOU ADD IN THOSE YOLKS
FOR THE FLAVOR AND THE COLOR.
MM-HMM.
SO NOW IT'S THICK ENOUGH.
YES.
WHAT TYPE OF PEPPER
DO WE HAVE?
THIS IS THE PASILLA CHILI.
GRILLED THEM, PEELED THEM.
TOOK THE SEEDS
AND THE RIBS OUT.
YEAH. AND STUFFED THEM
WITH QUESO FRESCO.
WE'LL BE DIPPING THE CHILI
INTO THE BATTER.
YOU COULD JUST THROW THAT
IN THE DEEP FRYER,
BUT YOU WANT TO DO
THE PAN-FRYING TO IT,
'CAUSE YOU WANT THAT LITTLE BIT
OF CRUST ON BOTH SIDES.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
SHE'S BROWN ON
BOTH SIDES--PERFECT.
RICE AND BEANS, CHILI FOR OUR
SAUCE THAT WE SAUTéED EARLIER.
AND YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE
THERE'S PLENTY OF SAUCE
ON THIS.
MMM, THAT
WAS A GREAT BITE.
NOT SPICY, VERY FLAVORFUL,
VERY RICH.
A LITTLE BIT OF THE EGG
BATTERING ON THE OUTSIDE,
YOU KNOW, KIND OF GIVES IT
A NICE CREAMINESS TO IT
OR HOLDS ONTO THE SAUCE.
YEAH.
WITH THE PASILLA PEPPER--
A NICE FRESH PEPPER,
A GOOD TEXTURE TO IT.
YES, CERTAIN THICKNESS
TO IT.
MMM, LOVE THAT
QUESO FRESCO.
WHAT DOES MAKE IT
IS THAT FRESH TOMATO SAUCE.
IT'S LIGHT, REALLY GOOD
TOMATO FLAVOR TO IT.
YEAH.
SO SIMPLE BUT SO GOOD.
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
HERE'S YOUR CHILE RELLENO.
THE CHILI IS SPICY AND HOT,
BUT NOT OVERBEARING.
THE CHEESE AND THE SAUCE
WITH THE CHILI--MAN.
THIS IS NOW
MY FAVORITE RESTAURANT.
SOPES ASADA.
YOU WILL NOT BE ABLE TO FIND
BETTER TAMALES ANYWHERE ELSE.
CHICKEN MOLE.
TELL EVERYBODY AT HOME.
YOU ACTUALLY PUT
YOUR RECOMMENDATIONS ON,
AND THEY COME HERE.
SEE? TOLD YOU.
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE NEED YOU
TO LET US KNOW,
SO HERE'S YOUR EXAMPLE.
COOL.
NEXT STOP...
PICK UP, NUMBER ONE.
WE'RE HEADING TO HOUSTON...
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
NEW YORK DELI.
ORDERING!
I LOVE
THE MISHMOSH SOUP.
MMM, THAT'S KILLER.
THANK YOU.
WHEN I THINK HOUSTON, TEXAS,
I THINK, WELL, THE GULF COAST.
I THINK ABOUT
THE HOUSTON OILERS--
NOT THE TEXANS--
BACK WHEN THEY WERE THE OILERS.
AND I THINK BARBECUE.
BUT WHAT I DON'T THINK
IS I DON'T THINK, LIKE,
FULL-BLOWN NEW YORK-STYLE DELI
IN A SHOPPING CENTER
NAMED KENNY & ZIGGY'S.
I HEAR ABOUT THIS PLACE,
AND I JUST GOTTA COME
AND GET SOME CORNED BEEF.
HOW MANY CORNED BEEFS
I GOT WORKING?
I THOUGHT NEW YORK WAS GOOD.
THIS IS THE TOPS.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
MA'AM, YOU SEE THAT?
LIKE A PICTURE.
I LOVE THIS PLACE--
LOVE IT.
SO MUCH THAT SHE E-MAILED ME,
AND SO DID SHE.
I COME HERE ALL THE TIME.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
THIS--LOX AND BAGELS.
LOX AND BAGELS?
THE MATZO BALL SOUP,
HUNGARIAN GOULASH.
MMM.
CHEESE BLINTZES
ARE REALLY GOOD.
YUM.
AS GOOD AS ANYWHERE
YOU'D GO IN NEW YORK.
THANKS TO ZIGGY.
THAT'D BE ZIGGY GRUBER.
PICK UP, NUMBER ONE.
ZIGGY BROUGHT AUTHENTIC
JEWISH DELICATESSEN TO HOUSTON.
I HAVE A FULL YIDDISH
DICTIONARY OVER HERE. YEAH.
THE MACH-ER.
(hacking) THE MACHER.
(hacking) MACHER?
RIGHT.
THE BIG SHOT AROUND HERE.
ORDERING KASHA VARNISHKAS
AND NOODLE KUGEL.
EVERYONE THINKS NEW YORK DELI
IS JUST CORNED BEEF
AND PASTRAMI,
BUT IT'S MORE THAN THAT.
IT'S THE TRADITIONAL STUFF.
JEWISH COMFORT FOOD LIKE
SOMETHING CALLED KREPLACH.
KREPLACH IS LIKE
A JEWISH WONTON...
STUFFED WITH BEEF.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE
THIS RAW BRISKET,
PUT TOMATO PURéE,
ONIONS, CELERY, CARROTS.
WE GET RID OF OUR ENDS
OF TOMATOES AND ONIONS.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE SALT,
PEPPER AND GARLIC MIXTURE.
WE'RE MAKING
BRISKET STEW?
WE'RE GONNA BOIL IT UP,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
DO IT FOR THREE HOURS.
COMES OUT OF THE POT,
OUT OF THIS SAVORY BROTH.
TAKE SOME
LAWRY'S SEASONING SALT,
AND THEN WE BAKE IT
FOR ANOTHER THREE HOURS.
TRY TO TELL
ME ALL OF THAT
WITH YOUR HANDS
BEHIND YOUR BACK.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
YOU'RE ITALIAN.
YEAH. HEY, COME ON,
I KNOW.
WE COULD GET
LOCKED UP LIKE THAT.
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT
OUR NICE HOT BRISKET.
BEAUTIFUL, RIGHT?
OH, LOOK AT
THE COLOR ON IT.
IS IT ILLEGAL
TO DO A LITTLE--MMM.
NO, YOU CAN DO
A LITTLE BIT.
OH, IT'S GOT
A TON OF FLAVOR.
THE BOIL ROAST...
MY UNCLE SEYMOUR'S
GONNA BE VERY UPSET
I GAVE
THE TRADE SECRETS OUT.
UNCLE SEYMOUR, IT'S OKAY.
I'M NOT GONNA TELL ANYBODY.
WE LET THIS COOL, TRIM ALL
THE SCHMALTZ OFF OF IT.
MMM.
THE WHOSE?
THE SCHMALTZ. IT'S FAT.
DON'T POINT AT ME
AND SAY "SCHMALTZ."
GONNA CUBE IT UP,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GRIND IT
WITH SOME CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
THAT'S GONNA BE
THE SWEETNESS.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA
GO TO THE MIXER.
TO THE MIXER.
GONNA CRANK UP?
YES, PLEASE.
WE'RE GOING TO ADD SOME EGGS,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER
AND GRANULATED GARLIC.
THAT'S IT.
WE'RE GONNA
LET IT COOL DOWN.
AND THEN WE MAKE
THE DOUGH?
RIGHT.
DIG IT.
NOW, ZIGGY, WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO DO ALL THIS?
MY GRANDFATHER.
I'M THIRD GENERATION
IN THIS BUSINESS.
WE'RE GONNA TURN THESE
INTO SQUARES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR KREPLACH FILLING,
AND WE'RE GONNA
MAKE BALLS OUT OF IT.
HOW'S THE FOLD OVER
GONNA GO ON THIS?
THEY'RE GONNA GO--
CORNER TO CORNER
OR FLAT OVER? OKAY.
CORNER TO CORNER.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA GO
AND STRETCH IT. STRETCH IT.
WHOA! STRETCH IT.
GO LIKE THIS
AND LIKE THAT.
MAKE SURE IT'S ALL
SEALED UP NICE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THESE
AND WE'RE GONNA BOIL 'EM UP,
SALTED WATER.
OKAY.
AND WHEN THEY RISE UP
TO THE TOP--
HOW DO THEY DO THAT AGAIN?
WHEN THEY...
(together) RISE UP
TO THE TOP...
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
OKAY.
SOME HEAD TO THE DEEP FRYER...
MMM.
ARE THESE READY?
MM-HMM.
THEN WE PUT THE APPLE SAUCE
AND THE SOUR CREAM,
AND GIVE IT A SHOT.
MMM.
THE CRUNCH OF THE DOUGH
AND THE SALTINESS OF THE MEAT--
I LIKE.
GOOD.
YOU CAN HAVE IT ALSO
WITH A MATZO BALL,
WHICH IS A MISHMOSH SOUP.
IT ALSO MEANS MIXED UP.
MMM.
THAT'S KILLER.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
YOU'LL LIKE THIS.
YEAH.
I REALLY LOVE THE MISHMOSH SOUP.
THE KREPLACH IS AMAZING.
EVERYTHING IS GREAT.
HOW IS THIS COMPARED
TO TRADITIONAL DELI?
THIS IS TRADITIONAL.
LINDA, PASTRAMI.
TOP PASTRAMI.
IT'S KILLER.
IT'S KILLER?
YEAH.
THEY HAVE HUGE SANDWICHES.
AS BIG AS MY HEAD.
OR BIGGER.
THIS IS CALLED
THE ZELLAGABETSKY.
(snorts)
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I GUESS I COULD JUST SIT THERE
AND WHITTLE AWAY AT IT.
HERE'S MY SANDWICH.
DELICIOUS.
THAT CORNED BEEF, BROTHER,
DESERVES TO BE ON
ITS OWN BREAD BY ITSELF.
LOVE THE CORNED BEEF.
THE KNISH NOSH--
POTATO KNISH,
CORNED BEEF AND SWISS CHEESE
MELTED ON TOP.
THIS IS A REUBEN,
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
SO HOW MANY CORNED BEEFS
DO YOU GO THROUGH A DAY?
ANYWHERE FROM 25 TO 45--
IN A DAY?
IN A DAY.
WE'VE BEEN PICKLING
OUR OWN BEEFS
FOR THREE GENERATIONS.
WE HAVE A LABORATORY
THAT MAKES THE CORNED BEEF
CURE FORMULA FOR US.
GRAB THIS. THAT'S IT.
HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
BRINE THIS FOR?
IT'S A 30-DAY PROCESS.
YOU AND I ARE GONNA SCHLEPP
IN MY GIGANTIC WALK-IN.
I GOT IT.
LET'S GO.
WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
RIGHT IN HERE.
OKAY.
THE SOLUTION--
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT IT OVER.
DURING THE PROCESS
YOU ADD MORE SOLUTION.
SO IT'S ALWAYS
GETTING ROTATED.
FIVE DAYS, THEN TEN DAYS,
THEN TEN DAYS, THEN TEN DAYS.
REALLY? WOW.
LOVE IT, MAN.
THIS ONE RIGHT HERE
IS READY TO COME OUT.
AND WE BOIL 'EM, AND THEN
WE PUT IT IN OUR STEAMER,
AND WE SERVE IT
TO THE CUSTOMER.
PULL ONE OUT.
AND YOU SLICE IT
TO ORDER.
SLICE IT TO ORDER.
TASTE THAT.
MMM.
FRESH RYE BREAD,
NICE DAB OF MUSTARD.
HOW MANY OUNCES
IS THAT?
10 OUNCES.
FANTASTIC. MMM. TENDER,
SLICED PERFECTLY THIN.
THAT'S AS GOOD AS ANY DELI
I'VE HAD IN NEW YORK.
THAT'S ACTUALLY BETTER.
GREAT JOB, MAN.
GOOD. THANKS,
CAN YOU HAVE TWO
OF THOSE LOADED IN THE BACK
OF THE '67 CAMARO
OUT FRONT?
NO PROBLEM.
VERY NICE.
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
IT'S THE BEST.
REALLY GOOD.
ONE GOULASH DINNER!
THIS IS MY CALLING, TO ELEVATE
EASTERN EUROPEAN JEWISH FOOD.
FROM THE BASICS...
THE STUFFED CABBAGE
IS GREAT.
REALLY?
OH, YEAH.
TO SOMETHING A LOT OF FOLKS
HAVE NEVER HEARD OF.
KASHA VARNISHKAS.
BUCKWHEAT? PASTA?
CAN YOU SAY CARBO-LOADING?
CAN YOU GET THAT
BY THE BUCKET FOR SALE?
(laughs)
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
AND SOME CHALLAH BREAD
AND RYE BREAD.
AT KENNY & ZIGGY'S
IN HOUSTON, TEXAS...
I NEED A PASTRAMI
AND CHOPPED LIVER!
NEW YORK DELI DUDE
ZIGGY GRUBER...
THANK YOU, MA'AM.
IS ON A MISSION.
I REALLY WANT PEOPLE
TO REMEMBER
THE WAY IT WAS LIKE
IN EASTERN EUROPE.
THE KREPLACH
IS AMAZING.
STUFFED CABBAGE, THAT IS JUST
THE MOST WONDERFUL THING.
LOVE THE BLINTZES.
THIS IS LOST FOOD.
AND IF NO ONE PERPETUATES IT,
IT'S GONNA DISAPPEAR
FOREVER.
AMEN, BROTHER.
ONE GOULASH DINNER
WITH KASHA VARNISHKAS!
KASHA FOR THE KASHA,
THE WHEAT,
AND THE VARNISHKAS
IS THE FARFALLE.
OKAY.
SO WE GOT SOME
BEAUTIFUL KASHA.
GOSH, THAT'S SOME
HARD GRAIN, HUH?
IT IS.
SO WE'RE GONNA
PUT THAT IN LIKE SO.
WE'RE GONNA BREAK SOME EGGS.
WE'RE GONNA SLOWLY ADD 'EM.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
DRY THIS ON THE STOVE.
THIS WILL BREAK
THE KERNELS
SO IT'LL BE READY
TO ABSORB THE LIQUID.
AND THE LIQUID
WE'RE GONNA ADD?
CHICKEN STOCK.
IT'S GONNA HAVE, ALSO,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
AND THE IT GOES
TO THE OVEN?
AND WE BAKE IT
FOR 45 MINUTES
AT AROUND 350.
THAT'S A KETTLE OF KASHA.
(grunting)
OH, BOY. YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA
COOL THIS DOWN.
NOW WHAT'S THE GIDDYAP?
WE'LL WE'RE GONNA
PUT ON A NICE GLOVE
'CAUSE WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND THE MUSHROOMS THAT
WE'VE ALREADY SAUTéED.
FARFALLE?
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S OVERCOOKED,
BY THE WAY.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE.
IT'S JEWISH FOOD.
(laughs)
I LIKE THE WAY
YOU ROLL, BABY.
SALT?
AND THEN THROW
THE WHOLE BAD BOY IN THERE.
YEAH. BUT YOU DON'T
WANT IT SPREAD AROUND?
NO, I'M GONNA MIX IT.
I'VE GOTTA MISHN.
GARLIC AND THEN PEPPER.
AND WE SERVE IT WITH
A LITTLE GRAVY ON THE SIDE.
WHAT'S YOUR GRAVY
MADE OUT OF?
THAT BRISKET JUICE
THAT WE WERE BOILING IT UP,
WE STRAIN IT. WE ADD
A LITTLE ROUX TO IT.
TIGHTEN IT UP,
AND THERE YOU GO.
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. A LITTLE
SWEETNESS TO IT.
MM-HMM.
THE CHICKEN STOCK
DEFINITELY COMES THROUGH.
AS MUCH AS I WANT THE FARFALLE,
THE BOW TIE PASTA,
TO BE FIRM
AND HAVE SOME TEXTURE,
IT WOULDN'T WORK
IN THIS.
THE KASHA'S THE ONE THAT
ACTUALLY HAS THE BITE TO IT.
RIGHT.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO MELD.
THAT'S WHAT
IT TASTES LIKE.
THE GRAVY, I COULD PUT
ON A FLIP-FLOP
AND I COULD EAT.
(laughs)
CAN YOU GET THAT
BY THE BUCKET FOR SALE?
(laughs)
MMM, THIS IS KILLER.
FANTASTIC.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
THAT YOU'LL FIND IT.
EXCEPT FOR IT BEING IN HOUSTON,
IT'S LIKE A NEW YORK DELI.
PICK UP!
WELL, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THIS PLACE IS OUTSTANDING.
YOU WERE VERY RIGHT
IN YOUR E-MAIL.
LISTEN, I NEED TWO
SMOKED FISH PLATTERS.
DELICIOUS.
I JUST HOPE I DO
MY FAMILY PROUD.
BROTHER, I THINK YOU'RE
DOING IT EVERY SINGLE DAY.
YOUR GRANDFATHER HAS
GOTTA BE FLIPPIN' BY NOW.
THANK YOU.
SO I TOLD YA, IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IS THE BEER COLD?
(all) YEAH!
WHO'S CRAZY?
(cheering)
(laughter)
WE'RE NEVER GONNA LEAVE.