HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
TWO OVER AND BAKED BEANS.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
FRENCH!
DINERS TIMES THREE...
PANCAKES.
IN SANTA CRUZ, CALIFORNIA...
THIS IS
AN EATING EXPERIENCE.
WHERE THEY'RE DOING
ALL THE CLASSICS...
HOW MANY ITEMS
ARE ON THIS?
AS MANY AS WE CAN FIT.
DINER-STYLE...
CORNED BEEF HASH.
AND VIETNAMESE...
SPRING ROLLS COMING UP.
MMM, IT'S GREAT PEANUT SAUCE.
EXCELLENT. THANK YOU.
IN NORMAN, OKLAHOMA...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
THE 110-YEAR-OLD LEGEND...
I LOVE THIS PLACE BECAUSE
IT'S BEEN AROUND FOREVER.
SERVING LEGENDARY CHILI...
WORLD-CLASS.
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING...
BEEF AND BEAN BURRITO.
MMM. THIS IS DYNAMITE, MAN.
THE LEADING CHARACTER IN THIS IS
THAT CHILI, 2-TIME STATE CHAMP.
AND OUTSIDE BOSTON...
ALL ABOARD!
(train whistles)
THE LUNCH CAR DINER...
THERE YOU GO.
CRANKIN' OUT LOCAL FAVORITES...
MEAT LOAF AND EGGS
IN THE MORNING, IT'S AWESOME.
AND, OH, YEAH...
IT'S A REGIONAL SPECIALTY.
FRENCH-CANADIAN, TOO.
(man) CORTON SANDWICH UP.
MMM. I'M MAKIN' THAT
WHEN I GET HOME.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
I LIKE ABOUT DINERS
IS THEY FILL A NEED, A NEED
OF THAT ALL-AMERICAN FOOD.
AND A LOT OF 'EM ARE
USUALLY OPEN 24 HOURS A DAY.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS
I REALLY DIG ABOUT DINERS
IS WHEN THEY HAVE
THAT EXTRA LITTLE FLAIR,
KINDA LIKE HERE
IN SANTA CRUZ, CALIFORNIA,
WHERE NEW JERSEY-STYLE DINER
MEETS ASIAN COOKING.
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT
SANTA CRUZ DINER.
SALMON BOWL COMING UP.
IS IT OFTEN
THAT YOU HAVE A SPRING ROLL
RIGHT BEFORE
YOU BUST INTO A BURGER?
THIS IS
AN EATING EXPERIENCE.
CHICKEN PHO.
IT'S HUGE AND VERY GOOD.
CORNED BEEF HASH.
THEY'VE GOT EVERYTHING.
EGGS BENEDICT.
SPICY THAI COCONUT SOUP.
THIS IS THE CRAZIEST MENU
I'VE EVER SEEN.
THANKS TO GIL KIRCHNER...
ALL RIGHT.
WHO GREW UP BACK EAST
IN DINER COUNTRY...
OKAY, THIS ONE, UP.
AND HIS WIFE KIM...
YEAH.
WHO WAS BORN IN VIETNAM.
TWO SPRING ROLLS
COMING UP.
WE MOVED OVER
TO THIS TOWN.
WE DIDN'T SEE THAT
THEY HAD A GOOD LOCAL DINER.
YOU GET THAT?
SO THEY OPENED ONE
BACK IN '98.
GOING OUT.
STEAMING BOWL.
HAD YOU BOTH BEEN
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
PRIOR TO THIS?
NO.
WHAT? NO EXPERIENCE
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS?
NO. BUT SHE COULD COOK.
SALMON BURGER
COMING UP!
BUT I LOVE TO COOK.
I GREW UP IN A BIG FAMILY.
WE SHARE RECIPES.
TOFU BOWL.
NOW SHE'S SHARING 'EM
WITH THE DINER CROWD...
MMM.
FROM RICE BOWLS
TO VIETNAMESE SPRING ROLLS...
THAT WAS EXCELLENT.
TO PHO, THE TRADITIONAL SOUP
KIM GREW UP WITH.
WE ARE GOING
TO MAKE PHO...
PHO.
SPELLED P-H-O.
P-H-O.
RICE NOODLE SOUP.
WE GET THE BEEF PHO,
AND IT TASTES REALLY GOOD.
WELL, LET'S GET STARTED.
OKAY, FIRST WE ROAST
THE SEASONING.
OKAY.
STAR ANISE SEED.
NOW STAR ANISE HAS KIND OF
A LICORICE FLAVOR TO IT.
YEAH.
OKAY.
AND THEN ABOUT TWO HANDFULS
OF THAT.
AND THIS IS THE...
CORIANDER.
CORIANDER. AND SOME CLOVES,
JUST A PINCH?
UH-HUH.
IS THAT THE RIGHT AMOUNT?
YES, UH-HUH.
DO I HAVE
MY RATIOS CORRECT?
YES.
THIS IS
WHAT I WANT YOU TO SEE.
CHECK THAT OUT.
THAT'S CINNAMON.
THIS IS
THE ACTUAL CINNAMON BARK.
SO HOW MUCH OF THIS
DO WE PUT IN?
YOU JUST BREAK IT UP.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT SMELLS GREAT.
AND ABOUT TEN OF THOSE.
THESE ARE CARDAMOM PODS.
YES.
IT HAS
THAT REALLY DISTINCT FLAVOR,
KINDA GIVES IT
THE--THE TANG.
AND ALL THAT TOASTING'S
REALLY GONNA OPEN THE FLAVOR.
YEAH, YOU CAN
ALREADY SMELL IT, YES.
YOU CAN START TO SMELL
THE PERFUME RIGHT NOW.
YOU JUST FILL THE BAG UP
WITH THESE, TIE IT OFF.
SO WE HAVE OUR SPICES READY.
NOW WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE ADD CHICKEN BONES.
YOU GOTTA MAKE THE BROTH.
UH-HUH.
THE BROTH
IS CHICKEN BASED.
CHICKEN BASED.
AND SO WE'RE GONNA LET THAT
SIT THERE AND SIMMER,
SKIM OFF ALL THE FAT.
AND THEN WE ADD...
THE ROASTED GINGER,
THE ROASTED ONIONS.
AND THAT ALL GOES IN, OKAY.
SOME OF THE DAIKON RADISH.
NOW SOME DAIKON.
A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT RADISH BITE TO IT.
NOW WHEN DOES THIS GO IN?
YOU CAN PUT IT IN NOW,
SOAK IT.
AND NEXT, WE ADD THE SALT.
THIS IS SUGAR.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S A FISH SAUCE.
WHOO! I ALMOST CHUGGED IT.
AND THIS IS THE KEY.
I'M DOWN
WITH THE FISH SAUCE.
AND THAT'S GONNA SLOWLY GO
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS,
AND THAT'S THE BASIS
FOR OUR PHO.
COOK THE RICE NOODLES.
SO THOSE ARE PRE-BLANCHED.
THIS IS THE EYE OF ROUND,
THINLY SLICED.
EYE OF ROUND, YEAH.
YEP.
PUT ON THE BEEF.
IT'S GONNA COOK THE MEAT
RIGHT WHEN THE HOT LIQUID
GETS ON THERE. LOOK AT THIS.
OH! MY MOUTH'S WATERING.
AND THEN WE ADD
CILANTRO AND ONIONS.
PUT ON SOME ONIONS.
THERE YOU GO.
WHEN IT COMES
TO THE TABLE,
YOU GET THIS
NICE LITTLE GOODY BASKET.
NOW I LIKE TO GET
MY THAI BASIL,
A COUPLE JALAPEÑOS, JUST
TO SPICE IT UP A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN SOME
OF THE BEAN SPROUTS--
THESE ARE ACTUALLY
MY FAVORITE.
I'LL SHOW YOU
ONE OF MY CHEATER TRICKS.
I WRAP IT AROUND THE CHOPSTICK,
AND THEN I GO...
MMM. OH, MY GOODNESS.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
THIS IS
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS.
GREAT NOODLE. THE BEEF, LOOK
HOW THIN THAT MEAT IS SLICED.
IT'S ENORMOUS FLAVOR,
YET IT'S VERY LIGHT. MMM.
THAT BROTH RIGHT THERE
IS AS GOOD AS YOU'LL FIND.
MMM! THAT IS CRAZY GOOD!
IN A DINER?
STEAMING BOWL OF PHO.
THERE IS A WARMTH
AND A HEARTINESS TO THE DISH.
IT ALL COMES TOGETHER
IN JUST A WONDERFUL BROTH.
IT'S A VERY
HOMEMADE TASTE.
OKAY, FOLKS, HERE WE GO.
THERE'S SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY.
AND THE ALFREDO.
GROWING UP ON THE EAST COAST,
EVERY DINER HAS A BIG MENU.
SAME HERE...
HOW MANY ITEMS
ARE ON THIS?
AS MANY AS WE CAN FIT.
FRENCH TOAST SPECIAL.
WE WANTS TO PUT THINGS ON,
AND I HAVE TO MAKE IT HAPPEN.
FROM DINER CLASSICS
LIKE OMELETS
TO LOCAL FAVORITES
LIKE SHRIMP AND SALMON CAKES.
WOW. YOU GO, GIRL.
SPRING ROLL.
BUT THE REAL KICKER HERE
IS STILL KIM'S
VIETNAMESE COMFORT FOOD.
NEVER SEEN A SPRING ROLL
ON A DINER MENU BEFORE.
MMM.
SPRING ROLLS. SO WHAT
ARE WE STARTING OFF WITH?
PORK.
SALTWATER?
I DON'T PUT SALT IN IT.
NOTHING?
I DON'T--I DON'T COOK
WITH A LOT OF SALT.
JUST BOILED IT IN WATER?
YES.
THIS WAS PORK LOIN.
YEAH. I SLICE THE MEAT.
AND YOU TAKE THE SHRIMP...
AND JUST BLANCH IN WATER.
AGAIN, I DON'T PUT SALT IN IT.
I KNOW. I'M NOT ASKING
FOR ANY MORE SALT FROM YOU.
OKAY, AND THEN WE SPLIT
THE SHRIMP IN HALF.
AND THAT MAKES IT
SO THEY'RE EASIER...
TO WRAP.
WHEN YOU WRAP 'EM.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN MAKING THESE?
AS LONG AS I REMEMBER.
READY TO BUILD ONE?
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE TAPIOCA PAPER,
WHICH LOOKS
LIKE A FOOD FRISBEE.
AND THEN WE RECONSTITUTE IT
IN SOME WARM WATER?
WARM WATER.
AND BY THE TIME IT STARTS
TO ABSORB THE WATER,
IT'S ABOUT READY--
TIME TO START ROLLING.
FIRST, WE START OUT
WITH THE LETTUCE
AND SOME RICE NOODLE--
KINDA SPREAD IT OUT--
AND NEXT IS THE PORK.
OKAY.
I LIKE
THE WAY THIS IS GOING.
AND THEN MINT,
ABOUT THREE LEAVES.
YOU PUT THE SHRIMP
LIKE HALFWAY.
PUT THE PINK SIDE OUT
SO YOU CAN SEE THE COLOR.
THAT'S WHAT I MEANT.
OKAY, WE START ROLLING.
JUST WRAP IT UP
AND THEN WRAP THE SIDE OVER.
THERE YOU GO. PERFECT! WOW.
YOU DID IT!
EH?
YOU JUST SLICE IT IN HALF,
PUT IT ON THE PLATE.
A LITTLE PEANUT SAUCE--
THE HOISIN SAUCE, THE WATER,
PEANUT BUTTER...
THE PEANUT BUTTER.
THEN YOU PUT SUGAR.
AND YOU PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
AND A LITTLE CORNSTARCH
TO TIGHTEN IT UP?
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
SPRINKLE SOME PEANUTS ON TOP,
AND JUST DIP IN.
AND THAT'S IT.
MMM. YOU DIDN'T SEASON
THE PORK OR THE SHRIMP.
IT'S GOT
ENOUGH FLAVOR--MMM--
THAT YOU DON'T NEED
TO PUT ANYTHING ELSE TO IT.
MY FAVORITE PART ABOUT IT
IS THE MINT.
IT SMELLS WONDERFUL.
AND IT'S REALLY BRIGHT.
IT'S GREAT PEANUT SAUCE.
MMM!
I'M GLAD THAT YOU LIKE IT.
EXCELLENT. THANK YOU.
TH-THANK YOU.
THE SPRING ROLL
IS WONDERFUL, REALLY GOOD.
(man) IT'S A GOOD MENU. THEY'RE
GREAT PEOPLE. YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
THERE YOU GO, SWEETIE.
DID YOU REALLY SAY TO YOURSELF,
"I WANT TO TAKE THE BEST
"OF THE EAST COAST DINERS,
AND I WANT TO TAKE
THE BEST OF ASIAN FOOD,
AND WE'LL PUT THEM TOGETHER?"
YES, THAT'S THE CONCEPT.
EXACTLY THAT.
YOU READY
TO OPEN ANOTHER ONE?
NO.
UP NEXT...
CHILI.
WE'RE HEADING TO OKLAHOMA
FOR A CHAMPIONSHIP BOWL.
TWO TIMES
OKLAHOMA STATE CHILI CHAMPION.
(mouthing words)
YOU KNOW,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ABOUT DOING TRIPLE "D"
IS CRUISING MAIN STREET,
MAIN STREET
OF SMALL-TOWN AMERICA.
NOW HERE I AM, 25 MILES SOUTH
OF OKLAHOMA CITY,
IN NORMAN, OKLAHOMA,
WHICH IS HOME TO O.U.--
YOU KNOW, THE SOONERS--
AND A 110-YEAR-OLD DINER
WHERE THEY'RE DOING A LOT MORE
THAN YOUR AVERAGE EGGS.
WELCOME TO THE DINER
THEY CALL THE DINER.
BEEF AND BEAN BURRITO.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
THE TAMALE BREAKFAST.
ONE OF THE BEST BREAKFAST FOODS
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
CHILI.
IT'S AWESOME.
I USUALLY GET IT
ON EVERYTHING I ORDER.
(laughing) THERE YOU GO.
I LOVE THIS PLACE BECAUSE
IT'S BEEN AROUND FOREVER.
BUT THE PREVIOUS OWNERS
COULDN'T MAKE A GO OF IT...
CAME TO WORK ONE DAY,
AND THE DOOR WAS LOCKED.
COMIN' UP.
BACK WHEN MARK AMSPACHER
WAS MANAGER HERE.
PANCAKES.
IT WAS LIKE
A LOSS IN THE FAMILY.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
SO ATTORNEY AND DINER REGULAR
BEN BENEDUM
MADE MARK AN OFFER.
BEN SAYS, "IF I TAKE CARE
OF THE LEGAL WORK,
WOULD YOU CONSIDER
BUYING THIS DINER?"
I SAID, "YOU GOT A DEAL."
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
AND ALMOST TWO DECADES LATER,
FOLKS ARE STILL PILIN' IN...
MMM.
FOR ALL
OF MARK'S DINER CLASSICS,
ESPECIALLY THIS ONE.
CHAMPIONSHIP CHILI.
IT'S WON THE STATE OF OKLAHOMA
CHILI CHAMPIONSHIP...
NOT ONCE, BUT TWICE.
I LOVE IT.
OKAY. OKAY,
WE'RE MAKING CHILI.
5 POUNDS OF GROUND BEEF.
A LITTLE 80/20.
NOW WE'RE NOT COOKING IT
ON THE FLATTOP, RIGHT?
WE'RE JUST
KIND OF ASSEMBLING,
AND THEN WE'LL COOK IT
ON A BURNER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA COOK
THAT MEAT DOWN FIRST?
NO. IT'S ALL GONNA
MESH TOGETHER.
SOME DICED TOMATOES.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
DUMP EVERYTHING IN?
YEP. THAT'S HOW WE DO IT.
(mouthing words)
TWO TIMES
OKLAHOMA STATE CHILI CHAMPION.
(mouthing words)
WE'RE GONNA PUT
DARK CHILI POWDER IN THERE,
GROUND CHILI PEPPER,
SOME PAPRIKA,
MAINLY FOR COLOR--
THAT'S WHERE THEY CALL IT
"THE BOWL OF RED"--
DICED FRESH ONION
IN THERE.
WHERE'D THIS RECIPE
COME FROM?
MY DAD AND MY GRANDDAD.
SOME FRESH PURéED GARLIC.
YOU CAN'T MAKE CHILI
WITHOUT SOME CUMIN.
I LIKE
WHERE THIS IS GOING.
I MEAN, YOU GOT ALL
THE RIGHT INGREDIENTS IN HERE.
WHERE DOES THE HEAT COME IN?
ARE WE GONNA GET ANY HEAT?
OH, THERE WE GO.
HO HO. CRUSHED RED.
WHOA. I LOVE YOUR REAL PRECISE
SCIENTIFIC MEASUREMENT STYLE.
THANK YOU.
SALT, GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE SUGAR.
PUT THE BUFFER ON IT.
SMOOTHING IT OUT.
NOW KICK THIS AROUND,
GET IT STARTED.
KEEP IT ON LOW HEAT.
AND YOU WANT TO TRY
AND KEEP IT COVERED.
SO YOU DON'T LOSE
ALL THE FLAVOR,
AND YOU ALSO STEAM IT
A LITTLE BIT.
STIR IT OFTEN.
EVERY 15, 20 MINUTES.
YEAH.
ABOUT TWO HOURS INTO COOKING,
I LIKE TO PUT
A COUPLE MORE TABLESPOONS
OF EACH OF THE SPICES.
SO WE'RE GONNA
HAMMER IT HOME.
YEAH, TO BE SURE
IT'S NICE AND TASTY.
THREE HOURS LATER,
THIS IS WHAT YOU GET.
LOOK AT THAT, MAN.
THERE YOU GO.
THERE'S CHILI.
MMM.
THIS IS DYNAMITE, MAN.
YOU KNOW, THE KEY TO THIS
IS IT'S COOKED DOWN SO WELL,
IT'S JUST GOT
A REALLY NICE GENTLE TEXTURE.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
IN THAT.
A LITTLE.
THAT'S
REALLY GOOD CHILI, BRO.
I LOVE IT
BECAUSE IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE CHILI IS THE BEST.
AWESOME. WORLD-CLASS,
IN MY OPINION.
WHAT ABOUT THE CHILI
MAKES IT SO GOOD?
JUST THE FLAVOR,
THE SPICE.
IT GOES GOOD ON ANYTHING.
(Mark) CHILI ON THE FRIES.
I ALWAYS GET MY HASH BROWNS
COVERED WITH CHILI AND CHEESE.
MMM.
THEY'RE FRITO CHILI PIE
IS AMAZING, REAL GOOD.
WORLD-FAMOUS CHILI DOG.
WORLD-FAMOUS?
IT'S GOT
FAMOUS CHILI ON IT.
MMM. DUDE, THAT'S
WINNER, WINNER HOT DOG DINNER.
(chuckles) I LOVE IT!
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
I THINK I'VE HAD
ABOUT EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
YOU KNOW, IT'S KINDA LIKE
STEPPING BACK IN TIME.
'CAUSE THIS JOINT'S BEEN HERE
FOR MORE THAN 100 YEARS,
WITH REGULARS WHO'VE
BEEN COMING IN FOR DECADES...
LONGER THAN I CAN REMEMBER.
FOR THE FOOD...
HERE WE GO.
AND THE FLOOR SHOW,
STARRING HEAD COOK
JUAN HERRERA.
THAT'S WHY WE ALWAYS SIT
AT THE COUNTER,
SO WE CAN WATCH HIM.
(Juan) THERE YOU GO.
BUT FOR A LOT OF FOLKS,
THIS IS THE DRAW.
THE BEST
GREEN CHILI SAUCE AROUND,
FROM, LIKE, NEW MEXICO,
YOU KNOW? LIKE--
WELL, IT'S NOT,
LIKE, SMUGGLED IN.
WELL, I KNOW.
"YOU KNOW, IT'S, LIKE,
SOME OF THE GOOD STUFF
FROM NEW MEXICO."
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
PRETTY MUCH JUAN'S.
SOME DICED GREEN CHILIES
THAT HAVE BEEN FROZEN.
WE'VE SEEN ENOUGH OF THOSE
IN NEW MEXICO.
THESE ARE
FROM ALBUQUERQUE.
TAKE SOME--
ARE WE DUMPING EVERYTHING
IN THE PAN AGAIN...
YES, YES, YES.
AND LETTING IT COOK SLOW?
I LIKE THIS.
CRUSHED-UP TOMATILLOS--WE'RE
GONNA USE ABOUT A HALF A CAN--
A LITTLE SALT,
CUMIN--CUMINO--
CORIANDER--
WHAT IS CORIANDER FROM?
CILANTRO.
IT'S THE SEED.
THE SEED, VERY GOOD.
THANK YOU
FOR THE CULINARY QUIZZING.
WELL, YOU KNOW.
PUT ABOUT TWO BIG ONIONS,
FRESH CRUSHED GARLIC,
NEXT...
CHICKEN STOCK?
WRONG.
REMEMBER THE GREEN CHILIES?
NOT "UNH-UNH," NOT "NOPE."
I GOT A "WRONG!"
WRONG.
YOU'RE OUT!
HA HA.
THAT'S WHAT I GOT.
A BUNCH OF JUICE
FROM THE GREEN CHILIES.
LAST, BUT NOT LEAST, OREGANO.
SO THIS GOES
FOR THREE HOURS.
YEAH.
WE LET IT
SLOW-SIMMER AND STIR.
YEAH. IT'LL COOK DOWN
THOSE ONIONS.
THEY'LL TURN INTO NICE...
TRANSLUCENT?
YEAH, THAT'S A GOOD WORD.
YOU READY TO TASTE THIS?
PLEASE.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
A LITTLE VINEGARY KICK.
GOT REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
SO WHAT DOES THAT GO ON TOP OF?
LOTS OF THINGS.
ONE OF 'EM WOULD BE
THE BEEF AND BEAN BURRITO.
MMM.
YEAH?
WE'RE GONNA HEAT UP
A FLOUR TOR-TEEL-YUH.
DO YOU REALLY CALL IT
A "TOR-TEEL-YUH"?
YEAH.
HE HAS
HIS OWN LITTLE LANGUAGE HERE.
I DON'T WANNA GET IT
TOO TOASTY,
BECAUSE THEN WHEN YOU START
THE ROLLING PROCESS, IT BREAKS.
IT CRACK-A-LACKS.
HE'S MAKING UP WORDS.
I'M MAKING UP WORDS.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A LITTLE CHILI
IN IT, SOME PINTO FRIJOLES--
THAT'S ANOTHER WORD
FOR BEAN--
SOAK THE DRIED PINTO
OVERNIGHT,
FILL YOUR COOKING VESSEL
WITH THE BEANS, ONION,
ADD SOME SPICES,
SIMMER 'EM ABOUT THREE HOURS.
IT'S SO MUCH BETTER
THAN BUYING A TIN CAN.
THAT'S A LEAN, MEAN
PINTO BEAN.
LET'S PUT
A LITTLE CHEESE, JALAPEÑO.
YOU READY?
YEP.
TOP IT
WITH SOME RANCHERO SAUCE.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
GARNISH THIS BAD BOY UP.
THAT'S A BEAUTY
RIGHT THERE.
TAKE A LOOKY-LOO.
REALLY GOOD. YOU HIT
ALL THE RIGHT PRINCIPLES.
THE BEANS ARE NICE AND TENDER
BUT NOT FALLING APART.
AND THE RANCHERO SAUCE--
NOT TOO SPICY.
THE LEADING CHARACTER
IN THIS, OF COURSE,
IS THAT CHILI,
2-TIME STATE CHAMP.
THIS IS,
LIKE, DINER-FARE-PLUS.
ALL RIGHT.
THE RANCHERO SAUCE,
YEAH, IT'S AWESOME.
GREEN SAUCE THERE,
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
DELICIOUS.
MMM.
IT'S JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO STOP IN AND EAT.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
I MEAN,
IT'S ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
THE BEST PLACE
IN TOWN.
HANDS-DOWN?
HANDS-DOWN.
YOU GOT A PLACE
TO PARK THAT CAMARO?
WE'LL BE HERE FOR A WEEK.
SURE.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
NEXT STOP...
NEW ENGLAND-STYLE DINER.
THIS IS WHAT WE LOVE.
MASSACHUSETTS...
SOME SUNNY ON THE ALL ABOARD.
A GREAT DINER.
DONE THEIR WAY.
(man) ALL ABOARD!
(train whistles)
25 MILES NORTH OF BOSTON,
IN THE NORTH SHORE AREA,
IS A TOWN CALLED PEABODY,
OR PEA-BUH-DY
IF YOU'RE FROM THIS AREA.
NOW THERE'S
THIS FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT WAS BUILT IN 1929
BY THE WORCESTER COMPANY,
THIS LITTLE LUNCH CAR.
IT WAS PLACED HERE
IN THE '50s.
IT'S CHANGED HANDS AND NAMES
A FEW TIMES,
BUT NOW IT'S CALLED
THE LITTLE DEPOT DINER,
AND FROM WHAT I HEAR,
I JUST GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
(man) ALL ABOARD!
(train whistles)
IT'S ECLECTIC.
TWO OVER AND BAKED BEANS.
THANK YOU.
A GREAT DINER.
OKAY, ORDER IN--
RIBS, BEAN, TWO SCRAMBLE.
IT JUST BRINGS ME BACK
TO WHEN I WAS A YOUNGER GIRL.
MEAT LOAF AND EGGS.
MEAT LOAF AND EGGS
IN THE MORNING, IT'S AWESOME.
NEW ENGLAND-STYLE DINER.
THIS IS WHAT WE LOVE.
OKAY, SO WE'RE
IN PEABODY.
WE'RE IN PEA-BUH-DY, YEP.
WHERE JIM MILES...
HERE WE GO.
AND HIS WIFE JUDY...
WHO'S STARTING?
BROUGHT A PIECE OF HISTORY
BACK TO LIFE...
IT'S A 1929
WORCESTER LUNCH CAR.
BEFORE THAT,
IT WAS ACTUALLY ON WHEELS.
IT'S BEEN ON A FOUNDATION
SINCE 1950.
AND FOLKS HAVE BEEN
JAMMING THE JOINT EVER SINCE.
SUNNY ON THE ALL ABOARD.
YOU CAN SIT DOWN. WITHIN FIVE
OR TEN MINUTES, IT'LL BE FULL.
NO CHEESE?
NO CHEESE.
GREAT LITTLE PLACE.
GREAT LITTLE MENU.
RIGHT DOWN
TO JUDY'S GRANDMA'S RECIPE
FOR A FRENCH-CANADIAN CLASSIC.
IT'S GROUND-UP PORK. IT'S
ALMOST LIKE A MEAT LOAF SPREAD.
IT'S A REGIONAL SPECIALTY.
AND THERE ARE SO MANY DIFFERENT
WAYS OF PRONOUNCING IT--
CORTON, CUTON, CRETON
AND HEADCHEESE.
DON'T ASK ME WHERE THEY CAME UP
WITH THE HEADCHEESE PART.
OKAY, SO LET'S GO
WITH, UH, CORTON.
CORTON, OKAY.
GROUND PORK BUTTS.
PORK BUTT.
PORK BUTT,
SO YOU'VE GOT THAT
REALLY DYNAMITE PORK FAT
THAT YOU LOVE
FROM THE PORK?
YEAH.
OKAY.
SEPARATE IT A LITTLE BIT
LIKE THAT, ONIONS.
SO WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO MAKE THIS?
MY MA MèRE, MY MOTHER.
AND EACH FRENCH FAMILY,
IT SEEMS, IN TOWN
HAS THEIR OWN LITTLE WAY
OF MAKING IT.
A LITTLE SALT, ALLSPICE.
OKAY, SO NUTMEG,
CINNAMON, CLOVE.
IT'S CALLED THE ALLSPICE
BECAUSE IT HAS
THAT VARIETY FLAVOR TO IT.
BUT THE MOST IMPORTANT PART
IS TO REMEMBER HOW MANY BALLS,
'CAUSE WE GOTTA TAKE 'EM OUT.
OKAY, 17.
NO, THERE'S 12.
EVERYTHING IS JUST KINDA COVERED
WITH WATER, ON THE STOVE.
HOW LONG WE GONNA
GO ON THE STOVE FOR?
THIS IS GONNA SIMMER
BETWEEN TWO AND FOUR HOURS.
HOW ARE WE
GONNA SERVE THIS?
I WAS BROUGHT UP
EATING IT
ON WHITE TOAST
WITH YELLOW MUSTARD.
DO YOU SERVE IT
COLD OR WARM?
I SERVE IT COLD.
I WILL EAT ALL THAT.
OKAY. I WILL WATCH.
(laughs)
WE WILL LAUGH
AND MAKE CHEER.
SO WE'RE COOLED DOWN, AND YOU
REALLY ARE GONNA DIG AROUND
FOR THE 17 ALLSPICE MARBLES?
12, 12.
SO...
ONE.
TWO. CAN YOU COUNT? THREE.
IF I GET MY SHOE OFF,
WE'LL GET OVER FIVE.
7. THAT'S 12, ISN'T IT?
2, 4, 7, 16.
6, 8. THERE'S 17.
(laughing) THERE'S 17.
AND NOTHING ELSE
GOES IN THIS, HUH?
IT'S SIMPLE.
PURéE IT A LITTLE BIT
SO IT'S KINDA LIKE
PâTé CONSISTENCY,
SPREAD IT IN
OUR LOVELY DISH HERE.
ALL RIGHT, THERE WE GO.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
IN THE FRIDGE,
TWO TO FOUR HOURS,
OR OVERNIGHT'S THE BEST.
LOOK AT THAT.
HERE WE GO.
HERE'S OUR SANDWICH.
NOW...
OKAY, SO YOU SAY YOU GO
A LITTLE MUSTARD ON THERE, HUH?
THERE YOU GO. CHEERS.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
I'M MAKIN' THAT
WHEN I GET HOME.
IT'S NICE TEXTURE.
IT'S SUBTLE FLAVOR.
THE ALLSPICE IS
AN INTERESTING BERRY
TO USE FOR IT.
I THINK YOU COULD DO
PEPPERCORN IN THERE.
I MEAN, YOU COULD GO
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THAT'S GREAT. IT'S JUST
SIMPLE AND GREAT. CORTON.
THANK YOU. CORTON.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT TAKES ME BACK
TO WHEN I WAS YOUNGER.
ALL ABOARD!
(train whistles)
GREAT PERSONALITIES,
AWESOME FOOD.
I WANTED TO LET THE CUSTOMERS
KNOW THAT I'M MAKING AN EFFORT
TO ENTERTAIN THEM,
COOK 'EM SOME GOOD FOOD.
WE'RE ALL SET THERE.
WHATEVER THEY WANT.
WE HAVE A TRAIN WRECK.
CORNED BEEF HASH, HOME FRIES
AND BAKED BEANS,
ALL THE THINGS
I LOVE TO EAT.
CHOP SUEY SANDWICH UP.
OKAY, I GOT ANOTHER BOWL
OF THE MULLIGATAWNY SOUP.
UNBELIEVABLE. IT GIVES YOU
A WARM, HOMEY FEELING.
MULLIGATAWNY SOUP.
JUST A REALLY GOOD,
EASY SOUP TO MAKE.
AND EVERYBODY LOVES IT.
OKAY.
FIRST, WE START OFF
WITH SOME BUTTER.
SO WE HAVE ANY HEAT
ON THAT THERE, SUNSHINE?
OH, NO. I GUESS YOU NEED HEAT.
OUR ONIONS, CELERY, CARROTS.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT
SIMMER DOWN
TILL EVERYTHING GETS
A LITTLE TRANSPARENT.
SO IT'S ALL
A LITTLE TRANSLUCENT NOW.
YEAH. OUR FLOUR...
A LITTLE ROUX.
CURRY.
AND THAT'S JUST A REGULAR,
LIKE, MADRAS CURRY.
YES, IT IS. CHICKEN STOCK.
MMM.
THERE WE GO.
WOULD YOU LIKE
THE CHICKEN, TOO?
WHITE RICE--THAT'S ALL COOKED.
YEAH, SURE.
CHICKEN BREAST THAT'S BEEN
COOKED, CUBED AND COOLED.
YEAH.
THYME, A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
FOR OUR SPECIAL INGREDIENT...
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT ARE THESE?
THAT--GUESS WHAT.
THOUGHT IT WAS
CHAYOTE AT FIRST,
BUT IT'S--IT'S AN APPLE.
GRANNY SMITH APPLES.
IN SOUP.
I'VE NEVER HAD THAT.
WE'RE GONNA LET
THAT ALL SIMMER DOWN
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
OKAY. SO NOW IT'S HAD A CHANCE
TO KINDA SIMMER A BIT.
AND WE ADD THE HEAVY CREAM JUST
TO TAKE THE EDGE OFF THE CURRY.
MULLIGATAWNY SOUP.
IT'S READY TO SERVE.
(blows) MMM.
WOW, THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THAT CURRY
DOES IT EXACTLY RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THE APPLE?
I LIKE APPLE PIE.
I'LL MAKE YOU ONE.
HERE GOES THE APPLE.
MMM. I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE APPLE FLAVOR,
BUT IT ACTUALLY KINDA REMINDS ME
A LITTLE BIT LIKE A SQUASH.
YEAH.
WOW. ALL HOMEMADE.
THAT IS SO GOOD!
WE'RE ALL SET?
I'M STILL EATIN'.
(laughing) OH, I'M SORRY!
JUST ONE MORE BITE,
'CAUSE I DON'T LIKE IT.
WHAT? WOULD YOU
TURN THE CAMERA OFF?
(chuckles)
IT'S DELICIOUS. IT HAS A REALLY
NICE FALL FLAVOR TO IT.
I LOVE THE APPLES.
A LITTLE BIT OF CURRY IN THERE.
IT'S AMAZING.
THE FOOD IS GOOD,
AND THAT'S WHAT COUNTS.
FIRST TIME SOMEBODY COMES IN,
WHAT SHOULD THEY TRY?
PROBABLY THE BAKED BEANS.
SIDE OF BEANS.
THIS IS THE REAL BOSTON
BAKED BEAN RECIPE, I THINK.
AND I'M CHECKIN' IT OUT
WHEN WE COME BACK.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
ISN'T THAT NICE?
MMM.
EVERYTHING GOOD?
(man) YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
AT THE LITTLE DEPOT DINER
IN PEABODY, MASSACHUSETTS...
(Jim) ALL ABOARD!
EGG WHITE OMELET.
JUDY MILES
AND HER HUSBAND JIM...
ORDER IN, JUDE.
ARE DOIN' THE DINER THING...
MMM.
NEW ENGLAND STYLE.
SIDE OF BEANS ON FIVE.
BOSTON BAKED BEANS,
NOTHING LIKE IT.
BIG BREAKFAST ITEM?
WE SELL MORE IN BREAKFAST
THAN WE DO FOR LUNCH.
THAT'S YOUR SECOND BOWL
OF BEANS.
IT'S A GOOD MEAL.
WHAT CAN I SAY?
WE HAVE SOME DRIED BEANS.
NAVY PEA BEAN.
I SOAK 'EM OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE DRAIN 'EM, NOW WE'RE
GONNA START MAKING THE BEANS.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME WATER TO THESE.
I TRY TO FIND THE MEATIEST
SALT PORK I CAN FIND.
I CUT THE RIND OFF...
RIGHT.
PUT IN THE RIND
FROM THE SALT PORK,
THEN I CHOP THIS UP,
AND WE'LL PUT THAT IN LATER.
NOW WE JUST ADD
SOME BAKING SODA.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA BRING IT
TO A BOIL, TURN IT DOWN
AND LET IT SIMMER
FOR 12 MINUTES.
NOT 11? NOT 13?
NOPE. NO.
12.
12 IS THE NUMBER.
ONCE IT BRINGS THIS TO A BOIL,
THE BAKING SODA,
IT'S JUST A BIG FOAM.
SO DO YOU EVER
TAKE THE FOAM HOME?
E.T. DID.
NOW THAT WE
SIMMERED THE BEANS,
WE'RE GONNA STRAIN
THE JUICE OUT.
CHUG! CHUG!
FIRST THING IS MOLASSES.
WHOA.
THE NEXT ONE I USUALLY PUT IN
IS MUSTARD, BROWN SUGAR.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT. THIS IS THE REAL
BOSTON BAKED BEAN RECIPES.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF KETCHUP.
AND THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE GONNA USE FOR OUR BEANS.
NOW WE JUST GOTTA
SET UP THE BEAN PART.
WINNIE THE POOH CALLED.
HE WANTS HIS POT BACK.
A NICE MOO.
WE'RE GONNA LINE THE BOTTOM
OF THE POT WITH ONIONS.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO DO THIS?
BETTY CROCKER,
I THINK IT WAS.
REALLY?
YEAH, I'M SERIOUS.
IT WAS REALLY A BETTY CROCKER?
YOU WENT TO SCHOOL WITH HER?
YEAH.
THEN WE TAKE THE SALT PORK
THAT WE HAD CUT UP,
JUST LAYER IT RIGHT IN THERE
LIKE THAT, AND THAT'S IT.
NO. SERIOUSLY?
THAT'S IT. NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME OF THE BEANS.
WE'RE NOT GONNA CONTINUE
TO LAYER THIS, ARE WE?
HECK, YEAH.
GET ABOUT HALFWAY UP.
OKAY, YOU'RE DOING
ANOTHER LAYER?
AND THEN
SOME MORE SALT PORK.
OH, DO IT RIGHT THERE.
OH, ALL RIGHT, LET'S...
ANOTHER LAYER OF BEANS.
NOW HOW OFTEN
DO YOU MAKE THIS?
I MAKE 8 QUARTS IN A BATCH
2 OR 3 TIMES A WEEK.
HOW LONG
ARE WE GONNA BAKE THIS?
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT
FOR FIVE TO SIX HOURS.
300 DEGREES, 5 TO 6 HOURS.
YEP. 5 TO 6 HOURS.
OKAY.
ARE THESE THINGS READY?
YEAH, GUARANTEE
THAT'LL BE WICKED GOOD.
ISN'T THAT A DEVO SONG?
OH, THAT'S "WHIP IT."
WH--"WHIP IT."
MMM, THAT SMELLS AWESOME.
MMM. THE BEANS
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH,
THE SAUCE IS SUPER CREAMY,
NOT OVERSWEET.
THIS HERE
IS THE REAL DEAL.
IT IS.
I COULD USE
A LITTLE MORE SALT.
I DO THAT SPECIFICALLY, 'CAUSE
SOME PEOPLE DON'T LIKE SALT.
OH, YEAH.
WHERE'D THE ONIONS GO?
YOU'LL GET
LITTLE PIECES OF 'EM,
BUT FOR THE MOST PART,
THEY JUST BOIL AWAY.
MMM.
CAN'T BELIEVE THIS IS WHAT CAME
OUT OF WHAT WE PUT TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
NICE JOB.
THANKS.
ALL ABOARD.
(woman) QUITE DELICIOUS.
THEY'RE NOT TOO SWEET.
NOW, TOMMY,
HOW'D THEY DO ON THE BEANS?
OH, THEY'RE UNBELIEVABLE!
REALLY GOOD BEANS?
YEAH, SOME OF THE BEST BEANS
AROUND, NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
GOOD FOOD.
EVERYONE'S REALLY NICE.
STRAWBERRY PANCAKES.
I LOVE IT.
COME HERE ALL THE TIME.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
GREAT SELECTION.
JUST A HOME-COOKED MEAL.
THERE ISN'T A DAY THAT GOES BY
THAT WE DON'T SIT HERE AT WORK
AND LAUGH
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME,
AND THE MAIN OBJECTIVE
IS TO MAKE SURE
THAT EVERYBODY LEAVES HERE
HAPPY AND SMILING.
LET'S GO!
(train whistles)
SO WAS THAT
A KILLER ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
DON'T WORRY.
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HEY, WHOA, YAHTZEE.
HEY, I FOUND IT.
YOU FOUND IT.
THERE'S THE 17th BALL.
IT WAS IN THERE. I DIDN'T KNOW
IF I'D GET IT, BUT I FOUND IT.
WHOO-HOO!
(chuckles)