HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
PSYCH. (laughs)
BURGERS, TACOS, AND DOGS.
YES!
IN HOUSTON...
IT'S ALWAYS SPECTACULAR.
A BURGER DIVE...
THEY'RE DEFINITELY NOT
YOUR COOKIE-CUTTER BURGER.
THAT'S A LOCAL LEGEND.
IT'S MADE
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
TELL ME WHAT YOU NEED, BOYS.
AND THIS PLACE IS HOT.
FIREHOUSE BURGER.
IT WILL SET YOUR MOUTH ON FIRE.
MMM. OH, GOSH!
IN MILWAUKEE...
TWO ENCHILADAS,
CARNE ASADA.
WHERE MEXICAN FOOD...
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
MEANS DUCK TACOS...
MMM.
AND ALL KINDS OF MOLES.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT MOLES
DO YOU MAKE?
WE MAKE
ABOUT EIGHT OF 'EM.
AT MOST PLACES,
YOU GET ONE.
MMM.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
THAT'S EXCELLENT.
AND IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA...
SO MANY DIFFERENT KINDS
OF FLAVORS.
HOT DOGS...
GOT A CHICAGO DOG.
FROM EVERYWHERE...
THE TERIYAKI DOG,
WHICH IS FROM JAPAN.
FRIED, BACON-WRAPPED...
YUM.
EVEN IN A BURRITO.
MMM. OH, YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN THE MIDTOWN
NEIGHBORHOOD OF HOUSTON, TEXAS--
NOW IT'S ALSO BEEN KNOWN
AS MONTROSE
OR THE OLD FOURTH WARD--
TO VISIT A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT OPENED AS A GROCERY STORE
BACK IN '39.
NOW IN THE EARLY '70s,
THEY STARTED SERVING SANDWICHES.
THEN IN '77,
THEY INTRODUCED THE BURGER.
THE REST IS HISTORY.
THIS IS LANKFORD GROCERY.
THE BEST HAMBURGER YOU WILL
EVER EAT IN YOUR ENTIRE LIFE.
WHOO!
IT'S MADE
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
TELL ME WHAT YOU NEED, BOYS.
...BY OWNER AND LOCAL LEGEND
EYDIE LANKFORD PRIOR.
A LOT OF BURGERS.
SHE GREW UP HERE.
THE FRONT PART
WAS THE GROCERY STORE.
THIS WAS OUR KITCHEN,
AND WE LIVED UPSTAIRS.
HI, GUYS.
AND IT WAS EYDIE'S DAD WHO
STARTED SERVING THE BURGERS
BACK IN '77.
THE BURGERS TOOK OVER,
AND THEN IT JUST STARTED
GETTIN' BIGGER AND BIGGER.
OKAY, Y'ALL ENJOY.
IT'S ALL MADE TO ORDER.
...TEN DIFFERENT WAYS.
OKAY, YOU GUYS.
FROM THE SOUTH
OF THE BORDER BURGER...
AVOCADOS, PICO DE GALLO--
IT'S ALWAYS SPECTACULAR.
TO THE DOUBLE BACON
CHEDDAR BURGER...
IT'S A GIANT BURGER.
IT'S GREAT.
TO THE HOUSE SPECIAL.
FIREHOUSE BURGER.
IT WILL SET YOUR MOUTH
ON FIRE.
BECAUSE IT'S LOADED
WITH A 3-PEPPER HOT SAUCE.
LOOKS LIKE MUSTARD,
BUT IT'S NOT.
I'M ACTUALLY NERVOUS
AT THIS POINT.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
FIREHOUSE SAUCE FOR YOU.
VINEGAR. ADD SERRANO,
JALAPEÑOS AND HABANEROS.
OKAY.
DID I SEE HABANERO PLANTS
IN THE BACK?
YOU SAW HABANEROS
IN THE BACK.
WE GROW OUR OWN,
BECAUSE WE WANT TO MAKE SURE
THEY'RE GOOD AND HOT.
GO BACK THERE AND PICK OUT
THE PRIME ONES.
PICK OUT THE ONES WE WANT
AND THROW IT IN THAT OLD POT.
THEY JUST COOK
TILL THEY'RE SOFT.
THESE ARE DONE.
MMM.
MM-HMM.
NO GLOVES OR ANYTHING
WITH THAT, EYDIE.
ABSOLUTELY NOT. WE'RE JUST
KINDA BLENDING THESE THINGS UP.
THERE IS NO WAY THAT THAT IS NOT
GONNA BE A MILLION DEGREES.
ALONG WITH THAT GOES
GARLIC, ONIONS, RADISHES.
YOU'RE JUST
GONNA LOVE IT.
THAT IS GOING
TO KILL MY MOUTH.
THERE WE GO.
THEN WE'RE GOING
TO POUR THIS IN HERE,
ADD SOME MUSTARD.
MUSTARD!
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
WE REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHERE THIS CAME FROM.
SOMEONE SAID,
"I WANT SOMETHING SPICY."
I WANT SOMETHING--
EYDIE CAME BACK HERE
AND WENT, "HA HA HA."
MM-HMM. MM-HMM.
AND THAT IS IT.
PART OF ME RIGHT NOW IS DYING
TO JUST TAKE A TASTE OF IT,
AND THE OTHER PART OF ME
IS JUST PRAYING THAT THE BUN
AND THE BURGER
AND ALL THE APPARATUS
WILL COOL IT DOWN ENOUGH.
WILL COOL IT DOWN.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT THIS ON THE BURGER?
YES, WE ARE. WE'RE COOKING
THE BURGER FOR THE FIREHOUSE.
SO THIS BURGER'S GONNA
GO SALT AND PEPPER.
WHAT ELSE GOES
ON THIS BURGER?
AND WE HAVE
OUR CAYENNE BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA MELT
A LITTLE BUTTER.
UH-HUH.
CAYENNE PEPPER
AND LET'S SEE...
OKEYDOKE.
QUIT LOOKIN' AT ME
AND ADDIN' MORE.
OOH.
I JUST WANT TO SEE IF YOU'RE
GONNA BE ABLE TO HANDLE THIS.
OKAY.
THAT BUTTER'S GONNA GO
RIGHT ON TOP OF THIS PATTY.
OOH, MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
SOME AMERICAN CHEESE.
WONDERFUL MUSTARD SAUCE.
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
JALAPEÑOS, LETTUCE.
SEE HOW QUICK SHE COVERED IT UP
WITH THE LETTUCE? "NOT THERE."
I DON'T WANT YOU
TO SEE IT.
ONIONS, TOMATOES, PICKLES,
AND THERE IT IS.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE LICKIN'
THE VOLCANO IN FLAVOR TOWN.
MMM.
OH, THAT IS HOT.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
OH, GOSH!
NICE HOT. I MEAN,
YOU STILL GET FLAVOR.
MY MOUTH IS, LIKE, LITERALLY
ON FIRE AT THIS POINT.
IF I JUST KEEP EATING, IT'LL
COOL IT FOR LIKE 20 SECONDS.
OH, MY TONGUE IS COMPLETELY
NUMB NOW. I ALMOST BIT IT OFF.
I BETCHA
THAT'S FLAMMABLE.
YOU COULD TAKE THAT SAUCE
AND PUT THAT ON RAW CHICKEN.
IT WOULD COOK IT.
(laughs)
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DIG THAT.
THE SPICES THEY USE--AMAZING.
I'M STARTIN' TO TEAR UP.
THEY'RE BURGER TEARS,
HAPPY TEARS.
THEY'RE DEFINITELY NOT
YOUR COOKIE-CUTTER BURGER.
CAN'T GET IT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
TWO DOUBLE MEAT CHEESEBURGERS.
HANDMADE LIKE YOUR
GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
...THE WAY THEY'VE BEEN
MAKIN' 'EM HERE SINCE '77.
YEAH, WE'D MAYBE COOK 10 A DAY,
AND THEN WE HAD TO DO 12.
THEN WE HAD TO DO 14.
NOW THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
MORE THAN 200 A DAY.
YOU GUYS, ENJOY.
THEY'LL COOK
ANYTHING THAT YOU WANT.
ESPECIALLY FOR THE REGULARS,
THEY CUSTOMIZE IT.
HEY, HERE WE GO, JORDAN.
SHE'LL EVEN NAME ONE
AFTER YOU.
"JIM BURGER."
THIS IS
THE ELUSIVE MR. GRIN.
WITH EYDIE'S HOMEMADE
MAC AND CHEESE...
WHY NOT PUT IT
ON THE BURGER
WITH JALAPEÑOS,
BACON AND EGG?
WELL, THEY ALL FIT
TOGETHER PRETTY NICELY.
THEY EITHER COME IN FOR
THE BURGER OR FOR THE SPECIAL.
WE ALWAYS GET
THE SPECIAL.
ON WEDNESDAYS,
YOU GET ENCHILADAS.
(man) THURSDAY IS
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK DAY.
WAIT A SECOND. YOU KNOW
THE SPECIALS BY HEART?
OH, YEAH.
WHAT'S
OUR SPECIAL TODAY?
TEXAS HASH.
TEXAS CHICKEN HASH.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
WHEN YOU COME TO TEXAS
AND YOU GET HASH,
YOU GONNA GET IT
WITH CHICKEN?
WELL, WE'RE HERE.
OKAY.
THIS IS MY THING.
IT'S MY THING!
WORD.
(giggling)
SEASON IT--
CHILI POWDER, GARLIC--
JUST A HANDFUL,
NO MEASUREMENT--
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLACK PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE THIS--
DON'T ASK ME HOW LONG--
JUST TILL I CAN
SMELL IT COOKED DONE.
YOU'RE A SMELL COOKER?
WHEN I CAN SMELL IT,
THEN I KNOW IT'S DONE.
SO NO OIL OR ANYTHING?
JUST POP IT IN THERE?
NO OIL.
YOU GOT THE CHICKEN FAT.
NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
WE'LL BRING THAT OUT
AND CHOP IT UP?
GONNA DICE THIS UP NICE,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
THE WHOLE FARM
ON THAT ONE THERE.
YEAH.
POTATOES, WE'RE GONNA BROWN
'EM UP KINDA, A LITTLE CRISPY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BELL PEPPER TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME ONIONS,
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
THIS CHICKEN. STIR THAT IN.
A LITTLE
TONY CHACHERE'S SEASONING.
JUST LET THAT CRISP UP?
HASH IS GOOD.
WE'RE GOING TO GET US
SOME OF THESE TORTILLAS,
FRIED REAL CRISP.
PUT THIS MIXTURE
ON TOP OF IT...
WHEN YOU SAID "HASH,"
I DIDN'T EXPECT THAT.
WITH A LITTLE QUESO
ON THE TOP.
WHAT'S IN THE QUESO?
MILK, BELL PEPPERS,
JALAPEÑOS
AND MAYBE
ONE OR TWO HABANEROS,
SLURRY OF
FLOUR AND MILK...
A LITTLE ROUX?
THICKEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT--
AND THE CHEESE,
AMERICAN CHEESE.
AND THAT'S IT, AND WE JUST KINDA
DRIZZLE THAT OVER THE TOP.
AND IT'S A LITTLE SPICY.
NO. HERE?
NO.
EYDIE'S, SPICY? NO.
TOMATOES AND AVOCADOS.
CRUNCH UP
THAT TORTILLA THERE.
OOH. THAT'S THE WAY
I LIKE IT RIGHT THERE.
MMM. AH, IT'S GREAT.
THAT'S SOME
RIGHTEOUS HASH, GIRL.
BUT YOU KNOW
WHAT THE KICKER IS HERE?
THE TORTILLAS.
IS THE T--ABSOLUTELY.
MM-HMM.
BUT THE EXTRA KICKER--
THAT CHEESE SAUCE.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A MEXICAN ALFREDO.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
GOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS KINDA
NEVER HIT OR MISS,
'CAUSE IT'S
ALWAYS A HIT.
OKAY, THE MEDIUM.
YOU NAME IT.
EVERYTHING TASTES GREAT.
PLENTY OF HABANERO.
THEY DO A FABULOUS JOB.
IT'S MADE WITH LOVING HANDS,
JUST LIKE MOM.
IT'S JUST
A GOOD OLD HOLE-IN-THE-WALL.
EVERYBODY'S NICE.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
ENJOY.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
OUR FAVORITE BURGER PLACE.
YOU, MY FRIEND--
I WILL TELL YOU SOMETHING--
HAVE DONE
AN OUTSTANDING JOB.
YOU HAVE A LOT
TO BE PROUD OF.
THANK YOU, SIR.
GREAT JOB. AMAZING.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING
THAT HAS THIS SPAN OF FLAVOR.
WE'RE HEADING EAST...
TACOS AL PASTOR.
FOR MEXICAN...
THEY HAVE
A DIFFERENT KIND OF SPIN.
IN MILWAUKEE.
MMM. IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
AN ORCHESTRA OF FLAVOR.
THAT RIGHT THERE JAMS.
I'M HERE IN MILWAUKEE--
LOWER EAST SIDE, TO BE EXACT.
ACTUALLY, TO BE MORE EXACT,
I'M HERE ON BRADY STREET,
A REALLY POPULAR AREA
AND NOT TOO FAR AWAY
FROM WHERE "LAVERNE & SHIRLEY"
RODE THEIR BIKE.
AND I'M NOT HERE TO TALK
ABOUT "LAVERNE & SHIRLEY"
OR THE GREAT CHEESE
OR THE BEER.
NOPE, I'M HERE TO TALK ABOUT
THE FOOD EVERYBODY EXPECTS
WHEN THEY COME TO MILWAUKEE...
(inhales) YOU'VE GOT IT--
AUTHENTIC MEXICAN.
THAT BRINGS ME
HERE TO THIS PLACE, CEMPAZUCHI.
I HEAR IT'S OFF THE HOOK.
TWO ENCHILADAS, CARNE ASADA.
TACOS AL GUSTO.
THEIR FOOD
IS JUST REALLY INTERESTING.
DUCK TACOS--
REALLY GOOD.
ONE PIPIAN COMING UP.
REAL MEXICAN FOOD.
IN MILWAUKEE.
...ALL THANKS TO
OWNER BRYCE CLARK...
ORDER UP.
WHO'S BEEN TRAVELING TO MEXICO
AND SEARCHING OUT RECIPES...
STEAK FAJITA.
FOR 16 YEARS.
WE WANT PEOPLE TO REMEMBER
WHAT THEY ATE IN MEXICO
AND SAY, "WOW,
YOU'RE DOING IT RIGHT HERE."
YOU'RE STILL GOING DOWN
TO MEXICO EVERY YEAR?
EVERY YEAR.
TRY TO FIND SOME NEW RESTAURANTS
THAT ARE OPEN,
MAYBE SOME OLD FAVORITES.
I USUALLY GO TO OAXACA...
THE SOUTHERN MEXICAN CITY
KNOWN FOR FLAVORFUL SAUCES
CALLED MOLES.
(man) MOLE POBLANO.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT MOLES
DO YOU MAKE?
WE MAKE
ABOUT EIGHT OF 'EM.
AT MOST PLACES,
YOU GET ONE.
THIS IS THE BEST MOLE POBLANO
THAT I'VE HAD OUTSIDE OF MEXICO.
MOLE POBLANO.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO FIRST?
GRILL SOME TOMATOES
AND TOMATILLOS,
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA CHAR A TORTILLA,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
CHAR SOME BREAD.
TAKE SOME ONIONS
AND SOME GARLIC,
AND WE'RE GONNA
CARAMELIZE THAT.
RIGHT. I DON'T EVEN NEED
TO GO TO THE GYM.
I CAN JUST DO THIS.
IT'S 19 TO 47 LAPS.
NEXT, WE'RE GONNA DO
ALL OF OUR SEEDS AND NUTS.
SESAME SEEDS,
PEANUTS, ALMONDS.
LET ME CHECK THESE
AND MAKE SURE
THAT THOSE ARE OKAY.
OH, I THINK
THEY'LL BE FINE.
CORIANDER AND SOME ANISE.
NO OIL.
YOU'RE TOASTING UP
THE SEEDS.
ALL FOR A SAUCE.
ANOTHER SAUTé PAN.
NOW YOU'VE GOT THE RAISINS,
PRUNES AND THEN THE PLANTAINS.
THIS IS
THE SWEET COMPONENT.
YOU GOT IT.
LOOK AT HIM GO.
LOOK AT HIM.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW I COULD DO IT
LEFT-HANDED, DID YOU?
HA HA.
OKAY, SO TOMATILLOS
COME OFF.
OKAY, THOSE ARE READY.
BEE-BOOP. NOW TIME
TO PLAY CHILI.
ANCHO, PASILLA
AND MULATO.
AND WE'RE GONNA
ROAST ALL THESE,
KINDA JUST TO RELEASE
SOME OF THE FLAVORS.
BRING OUT THE FLAVOR.
AND WE PUT 'EM IN A PAN
WITH SOME NICE HOT WATER.
THEY RECONSTITUTE.
BLEND 'EM FOR A WHILE,
ADD A LITTLE WATER.
SO THEY'RE PURéED.
TILL THEY'RE PURéED.
THEN WE PUT 'EM
THROUGH A STRAINER,
HEAT 'EM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY, BOSS, EVERYBODY'S
READY TO GO.
GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
BREAK UP THE TORTILLA
IN THERE AND SOME OF THIS.
ONE TOMATO...
ONE TOMATO.
A TOMATILLO.
THEY MAKE BIGGER BLENDERS.
I KNOW THEY DO.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
NOW DO YOU GUYS MAKE
YOUR OWN CHICKEN STOCK?
WE MAKE
OUR OWN CHICKEN STOCK.
NICE. KILLIN' THAT
POOR LITTLE BLENDER, THEY ARE.
IT LOOKS
LIKE PEANUT BUTTER.
YEAH, IT DOES.
WOW, THAT'S COOL.
WE STRAIN THAT OUT.
YOU WANT IT TO BE
NICE AND SMOOTH.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT THOSE TOGETHER.
ARE YOU REALLY USING
LARD HERE?
WE REALLY USE LARD.
YES!
TAKE OUR CHILI...
COOK THAT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
SO THERE'S THAT PURéED SAUCE.
GO, OKAY.
WE KINDA LET THAT SIMMER
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE BIT OF CHICKEN STOCK
AND THEN...
THAT'S THE MAGIC?
ABUELITA...
MEXICAN CHOCOLATE.
A LITTLE SALT, AND WE LET THAT
SIMMER FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
NOW WHAT DOES THIS MOLE
TYPICALLY GET SERVED ON?
TURKEY, WHICH IS A VERY
TRADITIONAL DISH IN MEXICO.
GO INTO RURAL MEXICO--
THERE'S TURKEYS EVERYWHERE.
OKAY, SO THE RICE
AND THE TURKEY ARE DONE,
AND THEN WE HIT THE MOLE.
A LITTLE TOASTED SESAME SEED.
MMM, DUDE. REALLY NICE,
GREAT COMPLEXITY.
GET THE VINEGAR,
GET THE SPICE, THE TANG OF IT.
MMM. IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
AN ORCHESTRA OF FLAVOR.
AND THAT RIGHT THERE,
I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S THE PHILHARMONIC,
OR IF IT'S METALLICA,
BUT THAT RIGHT THERE JAMS.
MMM.
THE MOLES
HAVE MORE OF A RICH TASTE.
POZOLE DE MARISCOS.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
FRESH, CLEAN, DELICIOUS.
DO YOU ALWAYS ORDER
THE SAME THING?
NO, THERE'S TOO MUCH
GOOD STUFF ON THE MENU
TO ALWAYS ORDER
THE SAME THING.
(Bryce) TWO FAJITAS.
THEY DO SOME THINGS
A LITTLE DIFFERENTLY.
GOTTA ADD OUR OWN
LITTLE FLAVOR TO IT.
JUST HAVE A TACO HERE
IS DIFFERENT
THAN A TACO EXPERIENCE
SOMEWHERE ELSE...
LIKE THIS ONE...
TACOS AL PASTOR.
WITH DUCK
INSTEAD OF PORK.
I GOT DUCK TACO.
WHERE DO YOU FIND DUCK
ON A MEXICAN MENU?
DUCK IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WHERE, I THINK,
SOME PEOPLE KINDA GO,
"DUCK--HEY, I'M NOT SURE."
BUT ONCE THEY HAVE 'EM...
IT'S ACTUALLY MY FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
MARINADE FOR
OUR DUCK TACOS.
VINEGAR, GARLIC.
WE GOT SOME CLOVES...
GARLIC, CLOVES.
SOME WHOLE CUMIN, AND THEN
WE'VE GOT OUR TWO CHILIES.
THE GUAJILLOS.
AND THE PASILLAS.
THE PASILLAS.
AND THE VINEGAR'S GONNA
KINDA RELEASE
SOME OF THAT STUFF IN THERE
AND GET THEM KINDA SOFT.
OKAY.
"SOME OF THAT STUFF"?
YEAH, THE STUFF
THAT CHILIES DO...
THAT THING...
THAT MAKES
EVERYTHING SO GOOD.
THAT VOODOO THAT YOU DO
THAT MAKES YOU WANT TO SHOO.
THAT'S RIGHT, YEP.
HOW LONG DOES THIS GO?
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR OR SO.
OKAY. BUT LOOK
AT THE PEPPERS,
HOW THEY KINDA RECONSTITUTE
BY SOAKING IN THE VINEGAR.
WOW, IT SMELLS KILLER.
YEAH, DOESN'T IT
SMELL GOOD?
YEAH.
PUT SOME OF THAT IN A BLENDER,
ADD A LITTLE LIQUID IN THERE.
HIT THE THROTTLE.
GO FULL SPEED. YOU ANIMAL.
THERE WE GO. LOOK OUT.
OKAY, CAN I TRY THIS?
THAT'S KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHY THEY CALL IT
"HAMBURGER HELPER."
I THINK IT TASTES GREAT
JUST BY ITSELF.
(laughs)
ADD A LITTLE OIL, THEN WE PUT
THAT ON THE STOVE AGAIN,
WE DO A LITTLE SAUTé
TO KINDA RELEASE ALL THAT STUFF,
ALL THE FLAVORS OUT.
BRING THE FLAVORS UP.
THEN WE TAKE DUCK BREAST,
CHOP IT UP.
THEN WE JUST TAKE THAT,
MARINATE IT WITH THE PASTOR.
WE'LL MIXY, MIXY, MIXY.
AND HOW LONG
DOES IT MARINATE?
IT DOESN'T HAVE
TO SIT REAL LONG.
NOW WHAT DO WE SERVE
THE DUCK ON?
BLUE CORNMEAL TORTILLAS
THAT WE MAKE HERE.
WE USE A LITTLE BLUE CORNMEAL,
PUT A LITTLE OIL IN THERE...
GOTTA ADD A LITTLE
FAT IN IT.
JUST A SPLASH OF WATER.
SO I DO NOT SEE
A TORTILLA PRESS.
WE DON'T HAVE ONE.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN GO
TO MEXICO AND GET THESE.
THEY'RE SO HEAVY.
OHH!
TAKE A LITTLE BALL THERE,
KIND FLATTEN IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
GIVE A LITTLE PATTY-PAT.
AND THEN YOU'RE JUST
GONNA USE THE PLATE?
AND I'M JUST GONNA
USE A PLATE,
AND THAT'S IT.
NICE RUSTIC-STYLE TORTILLA.
SO WE'LL COOK THESE WHILE
WE'RE COOKING THE AL PASTOR?
OH, YEAH.
WE USUALLY DO THREE
ON A PLATE. ONE, TWO AND...
OKAY. PEEKABOO.
THREE. I'LL GET
OUR DUCK GOING HERE.
WE'LL ADD
A LITTLE WATER TO IT.
THE TORTILLAS ARE SO BIG,
THEY LOOK LIKE PANCAKES.
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT
OF A CRUST ON THE DUCK.
RIGHT. I THINK THE DUCK
IS READY HERE, TORTILLAS.
THAT'S A SERVING.
TAKE A LITTLE ONION,
CILANTRO, A LITTLE PINEAPPLE.
TYPICAL CAST OF CHARACTERS.
AND THAT THING'S HUGE.
MM-MMM. WOW. I THINK
THE DUCK WORKS.
YOU DEFINITELY GET
THE TRADITIONAL
AL PASTOR FLAVOR TO IT.
GOOD STUFF, MAN. AND, OF COURSE,
YOU GARNISHED IT THE RIGHT WAY.
CLASSIC MEXICAN TACO.
MMM, THAT'S WHAT YOU SEE
EVERY DAY IN A TAQUERIA
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROAD
IN MEXICO...
EXACTLY.
DUCK.
AND YOU DON'T--DUCK.
VERY TASTY. A LITTLE MORE FLAVOR
AND A LITTLE MORE ZING TO IT.
THEY HAVE
A DIFFERENT KIND OF SPIN.
ENCHILADA OAXAQUENAS.
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
THERE'S NOTHING THAT HAS
THIS SPAN OF FLAVOR.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
ALL OF THIS
IS COMING FROM A DUDE
THAT WAS A FLORIST
FOR 20 YEARS
AND NOW HAS ONE OF
THE MOST SUCCESSFUL
MEXICAN RESTAURANTS
IN MILWAUKEE.
YOU'RE AWESOME.
NEXT STOP,
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA...
SO MANY DIFFERENT KINDS
TO CHOOSE FROM.
FOR JUST A BASIC HOT DOG.
DIFFERENT KINDS OF SAUCES.
THE HOUSE-MADE RELISH.
(man)
THE BALD EAGLE SAUCE.
MMM. MM-HMM... (mumbles)
IN THE WORLD
OF CULINARY TURF WARS,
THE SOUTH IS LAYING CLAIM
TO FRIED CHICKEN.
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA SAYS
THEY OWN THE MEXICAN FOOD.
AND NEW YORK CITY, WELL,
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE HOT DOG.
SO WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN A NEW JERSEY TRANSPLANT
OPENS UP A HOT DOG JOINT
IN RESEDA, CALIFORNIA,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF LOS ANGELES?
WELL, FROM WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE SAYING,
THIS DUDE IS KNOCKIN' IT
OUT OF THE PARK.
TIME TO CHECK OUT
FAB HOT DOGS.
(man) CHICAGO DOG.
(gasps) OH, YUM.
I DON'T EAT HOT DOGS
ANYWHERE BUT FAB'S.
THE REUBEN DOG--
CAN'T GO WRONG.
OKAY, WE GOT A POLISH...
A POLISH FIRECRACKER.
THERE'S NOTHING
QUITE LIKE IT ANYWHERE.
YOU THINK?
DEEP-FRIED, WRAPPED IN BACON,
EVEN DOUBLE DOG BURRITOS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THERE'S SO MANY
DIFFERENT KINDS OF FLAVORS...
SO MANY TOPPINGS,
IT'S AMAZING.
DIFFERENT KINDS OF SAUCES.
HOUSE-MADE RELISH...
PLUS, CHILI AND SLAW...
OH, MY GOD,
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
ONE GRILLED DOG.
WHIPPED UP FRESH EVERY DAY
BY THIS GUY...
OKAY, WE GOT
CONEY ADD KETCHUP FOR HERE.
JOE FABROCINI,
A 30-YEAR RESTAURANT VET.
MUSTARD.
HE LOVES HOT DOGS.
HE LOVES WHAT HE'S DOING.
WE GOT SOME IN THERE.
HE GREW UP IN NEW JERSEY
BUT FELL IN LOVE WITH DOGS
FROM ALL OVER THE PLACE.
AND I WOULD MAKE NOTES
EVERYWHERE I WENT
ABOUT DIFFERENT WAYS THEY MADE
HOT DOGS AROUND THE COUNTRY,
PUT 'EM ALL TOGETHER
IN A NOTEBOOK.
WE GOT A RIPPER.
BUT HIS FAVORITE'S STILL
THE ONE HE GREW UP WITH.
THIS PLACE, WITH THE RIPPERS,
WELL, IT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
WHAT IS "THE RIPPER"?
THE RIPPER IS
A SPECIALLY MADE HOT DOG
THAT I IMPORT FROM NEW JERSEY
THAT'S MADE FOR THE DEEP FRYER.
SFATTY SAUCE ON THE INSIDE.Y,
NO, IT'S NOT GREASY AT ALL,
NOT GREASY AT ALL.
EIGHT MINUTES IN A FRYER?
IT'S LIGHT AND CRUNCHY LIKE
NOTHING YOU EVER HAD, OKAY?
I'M THE ONLY ONE ON
THE WEST COAST THAT HAS 'EM.
WELL, LET'S TRY A RIPPER.
OKAY.
IT TAKES ABOUT EIGHT MINUTES
IN THE DEEP FRYER,
AND THIS IS
WHAT HAPPENS TO IT.
IT LOOKS INTERESTING.
IT GOES IN THE BUN.
NOW WHAT DO YOU PUT
ON THIS?
THE BALD EAGLE SAUCE.
IT'S MUSTARD RELISH.
BRING ME
THE BALD EAGLE SAUCE.
OKAY. SWEET RELISH,
SHREDDED CABBAGE,
SHREDDED CARROTS, GARLIC,
LITTLE BIT OF OREGANO--
A LITTLE BIT
GOES A LONG WAY.
IS THAT MEXICAN OREGANO?
THAT IS
WHOLE MEXICAN OREGANO.
MEXICAN OREGANO!
TWO POINTS FOR THE GUY
IN THE SHORTS
WITH THE FLIP-FLOPS.
HATCH CHILI POWDER...
YOU SEE THAT
UP IN NEW MEXICO.
DICED ONIONS.
WHOLE CELERY SEED,
CIDER VINEGAR.
WE GOT
A DIJON WHOLE GRAIN--
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
WE GOT DUSSELDORF MUSTARD.
OKAY THEN.
AND THERE YOU GO.
NOW HOW LONG DOES THIS TAKE
TO SET UP WITH THE FLAVOR?
ABOUT A DAY?
YEAH, I LIKE TO USE IT
THE NEXT DAY.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
MMM. OH, YEAH.
MM-HMM... (mumbles)
BALD EAGLE SAUCE--MONEY.
I'D JUST LIKE TO HAVE SOME OF
THE BALD EAGLE SAUCE ON A SALAD.
THIS HAS GOT TO BE
THE NEW VEGGIE ITEM HERE--
FAB DOG LETTUCE WRAPS.
(laughing)
DUDE, THAT'S KILLER!
FOUR LITTLE LETTUCE CUPS.
YOU HAVE SESAME SEEDS,
A COUPLE FRIED ONION CHUNKS.
LOOK AT THAT. OH!
I GOT A NEW DISH--
THE BALD EAGLE SALAD.
I WANT MY NAME ON IT.
HA HA, YOU GOT IT.
"THE 'TRIPLE D'
BALD EAGLE SALAD."
YOU GOT IT.
TWO BALD EAGLES.
IT IS DELICIOUS,
THE SOUR FLAVOR THAT MIXES
REALLY WELL WITH THE DOG.
IT WAS GREAT.
I NEVER THOUGHT
THERE COULD BE A DOG LIKE THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
SO MANY DIFFERENT KINDS
TO CHOOSE FROM.
THEY'RE FABULOUS.
THEY'RE JUST SO GOOD.
WE GOT A CHICAGO DOG.
I THINK YOU SHOULD HAVE A MAP UP
AND JUST TELL PEOPLE
WHERE THEY'RE TRAVELING
ON THE MENU OF MAP.
YEAH.
WE GOT
THE CAROLINA SLAW DOG...
THE TERIYAKI DOG,
IT'S FROM JAPAN.
TERIYAKI SAUCE AND RAW ONIONS
AND GRILLED PINEAPPLE--
PERFECT AMOUNT OF SWEET.
L.A. STREET DOG.
BEST THING ON THE MENU?
(all) L.A. STREET DOG.
IT'S OFF THE STREETS
OF L.A.
IT'S WHAT THEY SERVE
DOWNTOWN ON THE CARTS.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO HERE?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR ALL-BEEF DOG,
WRAP IT WITH BACON.
OH, NOW, SEE, I LIKE
THE BEGINNING OF THIS.
THIS RIGHT HERE, MY FRIEND, IS
THE BARBERSHOP IN FLAVOR TOWN.
SO THEN WE'RE GONNA
DROP IT IN THE OIL.
YOU WANT TO TAKE
SOME ONIONS AND PEPPERS.
NOW YOU ALREADY CARAMELIZED
BOTH OF THESE?
WE MAKE IT ALL DAY LONG.
SO EVERY DOG
IS MADE TO ORDER?
YOU DON'T HAVE,
LIKE, ANY PRE-DOGS...
NO.
IN A BUN
WRAPPED UP IN FOIL?
NO, EVERY DOG
IS MADE TO ORDER.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT OUT OF
THE OIL, PUT IT IN THE BUN...
OKAY.
A LITTLE MAYO...
ON THE DOG?
ON THE DOG--A LITTLE MUSTARD,
A LITTLE KETCHUP.
WE'RE GONNA GET
OUR PEPPERS AND ONIONS.
AND THEN WE GOT
JALAPEÑOS AND TOMATOES.
IT'S A HOT DOG!
JUST FOR A LITTLE COLOR.
I'M TELLING ALL YOUR FRIENDS
IN NEW JERSEY
YOU'RE PUTTING
THE WHOLE GARDEN ON THIS.
(laughs)
PSYCH.
MMM. WOW, MAN, THAT'S GREAT.
REALLY GOOD CRUNCH.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
INSIDE THAT DOG RIGHT THERE.
AND YOU CAN'T BEAT
THE BACON.
THE MAYO DEFINITELY
PLAYS IN, RIGHT?
YES.
IT'S THE RIGHT MIXTURE OF
INGREDIENTS. THAT'S A GREAT DOG.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT IS AN INCREDIBLE,
LIKE, MIX OF FLAVORS.
HOW CAN YOU POSSIBLY AVOID
A BACON-WRAPPED HOT DOG?
THE MARKET JUST WENT UP
ON DOGS AND BACON.
DO YOU MIND IF I CALL YOU
"WIZARD OF THE WEENIE"?
THAT'S OKAY.
I WANT YOU TO BE
"WEENIE WIZARD."
WEENIE WIZARD?
YEAH.
OKAY, WE GOT TWO CONEYS.
JOE IS GREAT.
GRILLED DOG.
HE JUST MAKES SURE
THAT EVERYTHING TASTES GOOD.
AND HE'S ALWAYS COMING UP
WITH DIFFERENT THINGS.
..LIKE THIS ONE.
YEAH, TWICE THE FUN
WITHOUT THE BUN...
WHEN WIZARDS GO WILD.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
IT LOOKS LIKE
A MEAT SALAD,
AND YOU JUST PUT ON
THE CORN CHIP CROUTON.
MANHATTAN DOG...
AT FAB HOT DOGS
IN RESEDA, CALIFORNIA,
JOE FABROCINI IS SERVING UP
DOGS FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
POLISH KANSAS CITY DOG,
A CHICAGO DOG.
YOU'RE MAKING SAUCES,
MAKING CHILI.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING LIKE THEM
ANYWHERE ELSE.
AND SOMETIMES,
ONE DOG JUST AIN'T ENOUGH.
THERE'S
FOUR DIFFERENT DOUBLE DOGS.
(Joe) TEXAS BURRITO DOG.
THAT ONE'S TWO STEAMED DOGS
TOPPED WITH JOE'S
HOMEMADE CHILI
IN A TORTILLA
THAT'S SLAPPED ON THE FLATTOP.
THE CHILI IS SPICIER HERE,
WHICH I LIKE.
THE CHILI IS GREAT.
IT JUST HAS A UNIQUE TASTE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
MAKE CHILI.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME OLIVE OIL IN THE PAN.
NOW IS THIS CONEY ISLAND?
THIS IS A COMBINATION
OF MOST OF THE STYLES
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
(scoffs)
REAL SPECIFIC THEN.
AND REAL SPECI--YEAH.
DICED ONIONS, CARROTS.
FOR A LITTLE
NATURAL SWEETNESS.
YOU WANT THESE
TO SWEAT A BIT.
THIS IS WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA STIR IT WITH?
THAT'S MY POTATO MASHER,
YEAH.
THROW A LITTLE SALT IN 'EM,
SPEED IT UP?
NO SALT.
NO SALT IN THIS?
YOU'LL SEE.
'CAUSE YOU'RE CELERY-SALTING IT,
AREN'T YOU?
NO, I'M NOT.
BEEF BASE?
YEAH, PREMIUM BEEF BASE.
HE IS JEDI MASTER.
HE IS WEENIE WIZARD.
NOW YOU GOTTA MASH IT ALL DOWN
WITH THE ONIONS, SOME WATER,
GROUND BEEF IN THE POOL.
NICE. I KNOW SOMEBODY
WHO USES THAT ONE.
YEAH. I BREAK UP
THE GROUND BEEF.
'CAUSE YOU WANT IT
NICE AND SMOOTH
SO IT LAYS OVER THE TOP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HATCH CHILI PEPPER...
I LIKE THAT.
THEN SOME PAPRIKA...
THIS PRECISE MEASURING STYLE
IS SO IMPRESSIVE.
YEAH--GROUND CUMIN--
ALL OF THAT...
WHATEVER.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
WHOLE MEXICAN OREGANO,
BLACK PEPPER,
WHITE VINEGAR.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
TILL IT'S
UP TO TEMPERATURE.
DON'T START WITH ME.
SO YOU'LL GET IT TO 165,
AND YOU'LL BE DONE?
YEP.
MUSTARD.
KETCHUP.
I'M GONNA GET YOU A POTATO
MASHER WITH A LONGER HANDLE.
IS THIS JUST BECOMING
A QUEST TO PUT
EVERYTHING YOU OWN IN THIS?
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT OF BROWN SUGAR--
IT'S JUST ABOUT LIKE THAT--
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
OOH, YOU PULLED OFF
THE SAFETY CAP.
NO SAFETY CAPS
AROUND HERE.
WHEN WIZARDS GO WILD.
JUST ONE MORE INGREDIENT
WHEN IT COMES UP TO TEMPERATURE,
A LITTLE BIT OF CORNMEAL
TO BIND IT.
SO WE'RE ALMOST DONE
WITH OUR CHILI,
SO WE'RE GONNA START BUILDING
OUR DOUBLE TEXAS BURRITO DOG.
THAT'S GOOD.
AND GET OUR STEAMED DOGS.
THESE ARE NATURAL CASING?
NATURAL CASING,
ALL-BEEF DOG--TWO OF 'EM.
AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT CHILI ON IT,
CHEDDAR CHEESE, FRESHLY GRATED,
A LITTLE ONION...
IT FEEDS NINE.
CORN CHIPS, A LITTLE BIT
OF BACON, A LITTLE MUSTARD.
AND ROLL IT UP, GRILL IT.
YOU GOTTA MAKE SURE
TO PUT THE BURRITO
WHERE YOU COOKED THE BACON.
GAIN SOME OF
THAT EXTRA FAT.
FLAVOR. SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR BURRITO DOG OFF THE GRILL.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT UP.
NOW, SEE, EVERYTHING'S
STARTING TO MELT IN THERE.
RIGHT.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
RAW ONION MAKES IT.
THAT'S A HUGE MEAL.
LOOK AT THE AMOUNT
OF JUICE, THOUGH,
THAT'S STEAMED IN THAT DOG.
THIS IS AWESOME, MAN.
AND YOU KNOW THE KICKER ON THAT
WAS THE GRILLING IT. GOOD STUFF.
THANK YOU.
A LOT OF INTERESTING FLAVORS
TO IT.
THAT CHILI'S GOT
THAT LITTLE EXTRA ZEST TO IT
TO REALLY PULL
THE DOG TOGETHER.
WE LOVE IT SO MUCH.
THERE YOU GO.
42 MILES TO GET
TO THIS DOG JOINT, 1 WAY.
NO. IT'S THAT GOOD?
YES.
IT'S THAT GOOD.
CHILI, ONIONS AND MUSTARD.
YOU THINK
THIS PLACE IS LEGIT?
OH, FOR SURE.
THIS IS TERRIFIC.
AT LEAST ONCE A WEEK,
SOMEBODY COMES UP
AND SAYS, "IT'S THE BEST DOG
I EVER HAD... IN MY LIFE."
REALLY?
SO WAS THAT
A KILLER ROAD TRIP, OR WHAT?
DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THIS IS
A TEXAS DRINK OF WATER.
(laughing hysterically)
THAT'S SO--YOU LOOK SO...
(continues laughing)
WHAT?