HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP,
YOU COULD SAY THAT AGAIN.
THAT'S POK POK?
THAT'S POK POK.
AT "TAP TAP" IN MIAMI BEACH.
THE ART AND THE FOOD,
IT IS JUST LIKE HOME.
(Guy)
HAITIAN COOKING.
FISH AND SHRIMP AND OXTAIL.
(Guy)
STRAIGHT FROM THE ISLAND.
TO DIE FOR,
THIS IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT IS SO LEGIT.
(Guy)
AT "NIKO NIKO'S" IN HOUSTON.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
(Guy)
GREEK HONEY BALLS,
OH, THESE ARE CRAZY.
AND SOME TRICKS OF THE TRADE.
UH-HUH.
I WANT ONE OF THESE FOR HOME.
(Guy)
BUT AT "POK POK"
IN PORTLAND...
EVERYTHING IS SO
UNIQUELY DIFFERENT.
(Guy)
THAI FAVORITES LIKE
GRILLED BOAR...
IT'S THE SPICIEST THING
ON THE MENU.
(Guy)
ALL DONE THE AUTHENTIC WAY.
MMM, LOOKS GOOD, HUH,
HUNGRY CAMERA, NOT TODAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
EVERY YEAR I COME DOWN
TO MIAMI
FOR THE SOUTH BEACH
FOOD AND WINE FEST,
I'VE CRUISED BY THIS JOINT
RIGHT HERE.
IT'S CALLED "TAP TAP,"
AND I'D SAY, "TAP TAP,
"WHAT IS IT,
MAYBE A TAPAS RESTAURANT?"
TAP TAP,
NO, A DINNER DANCE JOINT.
TAP TAP, MAYBE IT'S BEERS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
BUT THEN I HEAR THAT
IT'S THE ROCKIN' HAITIAN FOOD.
SO YOU KNOW I JUST GOTTA STOP
AND CHECK IT OUT.
HELLO, HELLO,
GRILLED CONCH.
WHEN I HAVE IT HERE,
IT ALWAYS REMINDS ME OF HAITI.
I HAVE NEVER HAD HAITIAN FOOD.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TRAVEL
TO HAITI TO GET IT.
COME TO "TAP TAP."
THE ART AND THE FOOD,
IT IS JUST LIKE HOME.
OKAY, FISH AND SHRIMP
AND OXTAIL.
GRILLED GOAT.
IT'S REALLY WONDERFUL.
WHAT INSPIRED YOU
TO OPEN "TAP TAP?"
THE HAITIAN PEOPLE
AND GREAT FOOD.
(Guy)
THAT OWNER KATHERINE KEAN
FELL IN LOVE WITH
WHEN SHE LIVED THERE
AS A FILMMAKER.
SO 15 YEARS AGO,
SHE OPENED THIS JOINT
AND HIRED HAITIAN-RAISED
GARY SANON-JULES.
HE USED TO WORK AS A BUSBOY.
(Guy)
NOW HE'S RUNNIN' THE PLACE
AND SERVIN' UP HAITIAN CLASSICS.
I'VE NEVER HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
WHAT IS YOUR FAVORITE
HAITIAN FOOD?
IT'S GRIOT.
GRIOT.
IT'S PORK.
DELICIOUS, IT'S AMAZING.
SO WE GOT A PORK SHOULDER,
BONE OUT...
NOT ONLY JUST ANY PORK,
JUST THIS KUROBUTA.
THE KOBE OF PIG,
THAT'S PRIME PIG.
THIS IS THE REAL STUFF.
TRIM THE FAT OFF OF IT,
CUT IT INTO CHUNKS.
OKAY, CAN I GET A MILK CRATE,
THIS IS JUST NOT GONNA WORK.
I ALREADY GOT A SORE NECK.
THROW SOME HOT WATER IN HERE.
IS THIS DONE WITH ALL MEAT?
SLIGHT VARIATIONS
BUT PRETTY MUCH WITH ALL MEAT.
SOUR ORANGE PULP
AND ALSO THE SKINS.
A LOT OF SOUR ORANGE
USED IN HAITIAN FOOD.
SOUR ORANGES IS LIKE
ALMOST IN EVERYTHING.
SALT ACTION.
AND SOME VINEGAR,
WE ARE PREPARING THIS.
WE'RE PREPARING IT.
NOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA BEGIN
MARINATING THE MEAT.
WHAT'S IN THE MARINADE?
SHALLOTS, GARLIC,
SCOTCH BONNET PEPPER,
FRESH PARSLEY, SALT,
SOUR ORANGE JUICE, OLIVE OIL.
THE GRIOT MARINADE
FOR THE KUROBUTA PORK.
SO ALL OF THOSE INGREDIENTS
GO IN.
HOW LONG WILL IT MARINATE?
OVERNIGHT
FOR THE FLAVOR TO SEEP IN.
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT
IN A STOCK POT, AND WE'LL
TOP IT WITH SOME OIL.
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT
FOR TWO HOURS.
AND THEN THIS IS WHAT WE GET,
BUT IT'S COOLED DOWN.
THEY REALLY DO
ALL THIS COOKING?
WE REALLY DO THIS,
I MEAN, THIS IS AN ART.
THIS IS MORE STEPS
THAN A FRENCH SAUCE.
FOR THE LONGEST TIME,
THIS WAS PASSED DOWN TO US.
THE PORK GOES DOWN?
THIS IS THE BAPTISM
OF THE PORK.
INTO HOT OIL?
IT COMES OUT GRIOT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SAUCE.
OIL, A LOT OF OIL.
THROW SOME GARLIC, ONIONS,
LET 'EM COOK DOWN.
ADD SOME CREOLE SAUCE,
TOMATO-BASED SAUCE.
IT'S GOT HERBS AND SPICES.
CREOLE IN THIS INSTANCE
DOESN'T NECESSARILY MEAN HOT.
READY FOR THE PORK?
YEP.
HAITIAN CARNITAS.
OKAY, SO YOU LET THIS
REDUCE A LITTLE BIT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
AND THEN WE HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE SALT.
TASTES PRETTY GOOD TO ME.
SO WHAT DO WE PLATE IT UP WITH?
A LITTLE RICE AND BEANS,
ADD THE GRIOT IN.
THE SAUCE GOES ON TOP
OF THE TWO.
THAT'S IT RIGHT THERE,
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
FANTASTIC DISH, BROUGHT THE
FLAVOR ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
CRUNCH OF THE PORK
ON THE OUTSIDE.
SUPER JUICY, MORE STEPS
THAN MOST PEOPLE WANNA TAKE,
EXTREMELY WORTH THE EFFORT,
YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
MMM, YOU WOULD LOVE THIS,
DON'T ANYBODY TOUCH THAT,
I WANT THAT TO GO.
EVERY BITE JUST MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
BY FAR THE BEST ON THE BEACH.
BON APPETIT!
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU,
VERY GOOD FOOD.
REALLY AUTHENTIC STUFF,
IT'S REALLY DIFFERENT.
(Guy)
LIKE ACCRA, A FRITTER MADE
WITH A CARIBBEAN ROOT VEGETABLE
CALLED MALANGA.
TASTES KINDA LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN A HUSHPUPPY
AND A FRIED SQUASH.
IT'S PREPARED WITH THE SAUCE
ON THE SIDE.
NOTHING LIKE I'VE TASTED
ANY PLACE ELSE.
(Guy)
BUT GET THIS! YOU WON'T FIND
THIS SAUCE IN HAITI.
OUR WATERCRESS PUREE,
THAT'S SORT OF OUR
NOUVEAU TAP TAP.
THIS IS KIND OF TAP TAP.
WHAT DO WE DO WITH WATERCRESS
IN THE 21st CENTURY?
THERE YOU GO, TRY IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF THE ACCRA.
I'VE HAD SIDE SAUCES
EVERY WAY, SHAPE, OR FORM.
THAT'S GOTTA BE
UP IN THE TOP FIVE EVER.
WHEN I GO BACK TO HAITI,
I'M LIKE, "WHERE IS THE SAUCE?"
(Guy)
BUT IT'S ABOUT THE ONLY THING
HERE YOU CAN'T GET IN HAITI.
IT'S A KIND OF A NOSTALGIC
TRIP FOR ME WHEN I COME HERE.
YOU GUYS KEEP ENJOYING
THE MEAL.
ALL OF THE RECIPES
FROM THE DIFFERENT PARTS
OF THE COUNTRY
ARE REFLECTED HERE.
(Guy)
LIKE THIS ONE.
A CENTRAL HAITIAN FISH CLASSIC
SERVED POACHED, GRILLED,
OR FRIED.
THE YELLOWTAIL, THE WAY
THAT THEY'VE PREPARED IT,
SO FLAVORFUL.
SO WE HAVE A BASE MARINADE,
OLIVE OIL, VINEGAR,
BOUILLON BASE, MUSTARD,
SHALLOTS, GARLIC, ONIONS.
START ADDING IN THE RED PEPPER.
SCOTCH BONNET PEPPERS,
SCALLIONS, PARSLEY,
AND FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
THEN YOU FORTIFY IT
FOR OTHER PROTEINS?
FOR FISH, LIME JUICE
AND SALT.
OUR SNAPPER HAS BEEN CLEANED
AND MARINATED.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE BROTH
THAT WE'RE COOKIN' IT IN.
THAT'S CORRECT.
SO WE START WITH THE CELERY.
RED PEPPER IN THERE,
SOME SCALLIONS, SOME ONIONS,
SCOTCH BONNET PEPPER,
WE'LL THROW A BLOCK
OF BUTTER IN THERE.
A BLOCK?
A BLOCK, BABY,
FRESH SQUEEZED LIME JUICE.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
PUT A LITTLE SALT IN THERE,
IT'S GONNA COME TO A BOIL.
WE HAVE A
YELLOWTAIL SNAPPER HERE.
BOIL POACH.
SO THAT'S GONNA BE IN THERE
FOR EIGHT TO TEN MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SCOTCH BONNET LIME SAUCE.
OKAY, THAT DOESN'T SCARE ME,
SCOTCH BONNET.
SOME OIL, GARLIC, SOME ONIONS,
RED BELL PEPPERS,
SQUEEZE SOME LIME IN THERE
AND BUTTER.
NOW WE'LL TAKE SOME WATER
FROM THE STOCK.
OH, YOU ARE GRABBING
A SCOTCH BONNET,
I'M GETTIN' NERVOUS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET HEAT
FROM IT,
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T PUNCTURE
THE SCOTCH BONNET PEPPER.
YOU DO GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE FLAVOR,
BUT NONE OF THE HEAT
UNTIL YOU OPEN IT UP
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT,
BUT WE LEAVE THAT
UP TO THE CUSTOMER.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
FISH IS DONE
IN THE HOT TUB SAUNA.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR SCOTCH BONNET LIME SAUCE
AND THEN WE'LL JUST
TOP THE FISH WITH IT.
BEAUTIFUL.
REALLY, YOU'VE GOT A LOT
OF COLORS TO IT.
THE LIME, JUST GO AHEAD
AND SQUEEZE IT RIGHT ON.
WHERE DO YOU LIKE
TO START EATING AT?
I LIKE THE KNEE.
I LIKE THE ELBOW.
SUBMERGE IT
IN A LITTLE SAUCE.
MMM, AH MAN, WOW!
I CREDIT YOU
FOR IT HAVING MASSIVE FLAVOR.
THE FISH IS UNBELIEVABLY TENDER.
THE SAUCE THAT GOES
ALONG WITH IT,
IT ALMOST HAS A FRENCH
INFLUENCE TO IT.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
MMM, I WANNA EAT IT ALL,
LISTEN TO ME RIGHT NOW.
YOU HAVE GOT TO COME
TRY THIS FISH,
EVEN IF YOU DON'T LIKE FISH.
IT IS SO LEGIT,
IT'S TOO LEGIT TO FISH.
TO DIE FOR,
THIS IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
"TAP TAP" IS AN ICON.
IT'S FANTASTIC, ORIGINAL,
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I'M MOVIN' IN, EARLIER I WAS
JUST GONNA COME AND STAY
FOR AWHILE.
NOW I'M MOVIN' IN.
OH, BEAUTIFUL, WELCOME.
CAN I PUT MY STUFF UP THERE?
(Guy)
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADIN' TO HOUSTON...
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS
THIS IS GREAT.
(Guy)
FOR A TASTE OF GREECE.
DEAD ON, THE FOOD'S AWESOME.
LAMB SHANK WITH POTATO.
MMM, THOSE ARE DELICIOUS.
I'M HERE IN THE MONTROSE AREA
OF HOUSTON, TEXAS,
AT A JOINT THAT'S
CENTRALLY LOCATED
TO RICE UNIVERSITY,
THE DOWNTOWN AREA,
AND THE GALLERIA MALL.
NOW THIS PLACE
IS SMOKIN' BUSY ALL THE TIME.
THE QUESTION IS, IS IT BECAUSE
OF THE LOCATION OR THE FOOD?
WE'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT
AS WE VISIT "NIKO NIKO'S."
THE FOOD, IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT IS JUST OUTSTANDING.
IT'S THE CLOSEST THING YOU CAN
COME TO EATING IN GREECE.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
I ENJOY IT SO MUCH
THAT I KEEP ON COMING BACK
SINCE 1977 WHEN THEY
FIRST OPENED THE DOORS.
I ACTUALLY USED TO WALK UP
AND ORDER HERE.
(Guy)
BACK WHEN
DIMITRI FETOKAKIS' PARENTS
FIRST OPENED THE PLACE.
I'VE BEEN WORKING IN HERE
SINCE I WAS FIVE.
THIS PART OF THE RESTAURANT
WAS OUR HOUSE.
THIS WAS ACTUALLY
WHERE YOU LIVED?
THAT'S RIGHT, YEAH.
HAD A GYRO MACHINE
AND A GRILL
AND THEN NIKO NIKO'S STARTED.
WE WERE DOING THE BASICS,
AND THEN WE KINDA WANTED
TO UPSCALE OUR MENU
A LITTLE BIT.
(Guy)
USING THE
WHOLE FAMILY COOKBOOK,
FROM GREEK MEATBALLS
TO THIS CLASSIC...
MOUSSAKA WHICH IS MY FAVORITE
(Guy)
TO THIS FAMILY FAVORITE.
THE LAMB SHANK WITH POTATO.
WHOSE LAMB SHANK RECIPE
IS THIS?
MY POP'S.
SO FIRST WE TRIM
SOME OF THE FAT.
BIG SELLER HERE?
VERY BIG SELLER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR MARINADE.
SO WE GOT LEMON JUICE,
GREEK OREGANO.
THIS IS FROM OUR ORCHARD
IN GREECE.
THIS IS BLOOMIN', MAN.
BLACK PEPPER, SEASON ALL.
A LITTLE SEASONED SALT,
FRESH GARLIC.
FRESH GARLIC, SALT,
AND OLIVE OIL, GREEK OLIVE OIL.
SO THIS IS A PRETTY
TRADITIONAL MARINADE.
SIMPLE.
AND HOW LONG
WILL WE MARINATE THOSE SHANKS?
WE USED TO MARINATE 'EM
24 HOURS.
BUT WE GOT A MARINATING MACHINE
TO SPEED UP THE PROCESS.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE THIS.
YEAH, IT'S COOL.
THIS IS A TUMBLER, WHICH WE
TOSS IN OUR LAMB SHANKS
AND JUST POUR OUR MARINADE.
CAP IT OFF WITH A HOSE.
SO NOW IT'S GONNA START
SUCKING THE AIR OUT.
RIGHT.
SO WHEN THE VACUUM GETS TO 20,
YOU TURN IT OFF,
LAY IT ON ITS SIDE.
AND THEN WE'LL LET IT DO ITS
WORK FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
MAKES IT SO IT'S EASIER FOR
THE MOISTURE TO PENETRATE IN.
UH-HUH.
I WANT ONE OF THESE FOR HOME.
THEN WE'LL JUST PUT IT
IN THE PAN.
THE SHANKS ARE LINED UP,
GET A LITTLE WATER ON TOP.
IT'S TIME TO COVER 'EM
AND GO IN THE OVEN.
HOW LONG IS IT GONNA
GO IN THE OVEN?
TWO HOURS AND THEN
WHAT WE'LL DO IS UNCOVER IT,
FLIP THE LAMB SHANKS,
AND THEN FOR ANOTHER HOUR.
LOOK AT THAT,
USUALLY TWO PEOPLE.
I'LL GET THE DOORS.
THANK YOU.
WOW, THOSE BAD BOYS
JUST COOKED DOWN ALL THE FAT.
IT'S CRAZY,
HOW MANY YOU GOT?
TWO.
AND WHAT'S THIS
BEING SERVED WITH?
THAT COMES WITH
A SMALL GREEK SALAD,
THE ROASTED POTATOES,
PITA BREAD, TZATZIKI SAUCE,
AND LEMON.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT,
THAT'S A REALLY NICE MARINADE
WITH THE LEMON JUICE.
PROBABLY ONE OF THE MORE
LEMON FORWARD LAMB SHANKS
I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO TAKE THIS AWAY, GREAT.
THANK YOU.
I WASN'T SERIOUS.
NO?
IT'S GOT A GREAT FLAVOR ON IT.
GOOD ALL AROUND GREEK FOOD.
THERE'S ALWAYS A CROWD,
THERE'S ALWAYS A LINE.
NEXT IN LINE, PLEASE BE READY.
I CAN HEAR THIS PLACE
GOING A MILLION MILES
AN HOUR OUT THERE?
DOES IT EVER SLOW DOWN?
I'M GLAD TO SAY NO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HOW MANY PITAS YOU GUYS
GO THROUGH IN A WEEK?
TWELVE THOUSAND.
AND THOSE BIG HUNKS
OF GYRO?
FIFTEEN A DAY.
OF THOSE?
UH-HUH.
(Guy)
AND A DOZEN SCRATCH MADE
DESSERTS FROM CLASSIC BAKLAVA...
VERY FLAKY AND IT'S FRESH.
(Guy)
TO SOMETHING MOST FOLKS
HAVE NEVER HEARD OF.
LOUKOUMADES.
NOW THAT I CAN SAY IT,
CAN YOU TELL ME WHAT IT IS?
GREEK HONEY BALLS.
GREEK HONEY BALLS, THAT'S IT,
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW.
SO WE GOT OUR FLOUR, SUGAR...
NOT VERY MUCH OF THAT.
NOT MUCH, SALT, VANILLA.
JUST A TOUCH, AND YEAST.
YEAST, WATER, 80 DEGREES.
EIGHTY DEGREES TO MAKE
THE CORRECT LOUKOUMADES.
SO WE PUT IT
ON LOW SPEED FIRST.
I'M OVER HERE.
IT LOOKS LIKE DOUGHNUT BATTER.
WELL, WE GOTTA LET IT RISE
FOR A WHILE, ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
YOU GOTTA LET THAT YEAST
ACTIVATE.
A BUNCH OF SIMMERING WATER.
WE'RE GONNA DO OUR SAUCE
FOR THE LOUKOUMADES.
WE CAN ALSO USE THIS
FOR THE BAKLAVA AND THE KATAIFI,
AND THE OTHER PASTRIES
THAT WE MAKE.
YOU SURE THAT'S ENOUGH SUGAR?
I DON'T KNOW, WE'LL SEE.
THEN WE TAKE SOME LEMON JUICE
AND CINNAMON STICK.
LET THAT COOK FOR ABOUT
1 1/2 HOURS.
AFTER THAT'S DONE,
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR HONEY.
SO YOU LET IT REDUCE DOWN
A LITTLE BIT MORE
AND THEN RIGHT BEFORE
YOU'RE READY TO TAKE IT
OFF THE HEAT,
YOU'LL HIT IT WITH THE HONEY?
WITH THE HONEY, THAT'S IT.
HONEY, SUGAR, CINNAMON, LEMON,
WATER, SYRUP, AND THAT'S IT.
WE GOT OUR DOUGH TO RISE.
NOW IT GOES INTO THIS BAD BOY,
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS A BELSHAW
DOUGHNUT MACHINE.
YOU JUST CRANK IT AND IT JUST
POPS OUT LITTLE DOUGHNUTS?
WE'LL COOK 'EM
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES,
WE'LL SEPARATE 'EM HERE.
LOOK AT THE WAY
THEY PUFFED UP SO QUICKLY.
THIS LITTLE APPARATUS
IS JUST TO MAKE LOUKOUMADES?
I WANT THAT ON THE BACK
OF THE '67.
SO WE'RE DONE WITH THESE,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE 'EM
AND PUT 'EM IN THE HONEY.
OH, THEY JUST GO RIGHT IN...
THAT'S IT.
DON'T MESS WITH 'EM?
NO, NO ABSOLUTELY NOT,
I WANT YOU TO MESS WITH 'EM.
MESS WITH 'EM,
DON'T MESS WITH 'EM.
MESS WITH 'EM.
AND THESE AREN'T GONNA
GET SOGGY?
THEY'RE STILL FLOATING.
NO, THAT'S FINE, WE WANT
ALL THE HONEY TO GET IN THERE.
THOSE ARE CULINARY BUOYS
IN THE SHIPYARD OF FLAVOR TOWN.
THEN TO TOP IT OFF, WE USE
POWDERED SUGAR AND CINNAMON.
WOW, DUDE, WATCH THIS,
IT JUST COMES RIGHT OUT.
THESE ARE CRAZY.
MMM, THEY FILL UP
WITH THAT JUICE INSIDE.
YOU BITE INTO THEM
AND THEY ALMOST POP.
GOOD?
GOOD, THOSE ARE NOT EVEN GOOD,
THOSE ARE GREAT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THESE
IN MY LIFE.
THIS ISN'T OVERLY SWEET,
THE LEMON IS THE FIRST THING
I RECOGNIZE.
YEAH.
THOSE ARE YOURS.
YOU REALLY NEED TO COME
TO NIKO NIKO'S.
NO SURPRISES, IT'S ALWAYS JUST
DEAD-ON, THE FOOD'S AWESOME.
IT HAS A LOT OF HEART
AND PERSONALITY.
IT'S EXCELLENT,
THIS IS AS GOOD AS MY MOM'S.
IT'S ONE OF MY
FAVORITE PLACES OF ALL TIME.
GOOD JOB, BROTHER.
THANKS MAN.
LIKE THAT ONE,
CAN I HAVE THE MACHINE?
YES, SIR, WHATEVER YOU WANT.
(Guy)
NEXT UP, WE'RE HEADIN' WEST.
UNIQUE FOOD
THAT'S REALLY TASTY.
(Guy)
WITH THE FAVORITES
THIS DUDE BROUGHT BACK
FROM SOUTHEAST ASIA.
WE ALSO LIKE THE PORK BELLY
AND THE PRAWNS.
MMM, WOW, THAT'S CRAZY,
EXCELLENT DISH, THANK YOU.
I'M HERE IN PORTLAND, OREGON,
WHERE YOU CAN ALWAYS EXPECT
A LITTLE RAIN AND A LOT
OF GREAT FOOD.
I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
THIS JOINT.
IT'S CALLED POK POK
WHERE THEY DON'T LET
A LITTLE RAIN KEEP THEM
FROM MAKING SOME
KILLER THAI FOOD.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA START
CALLIN' THE SHOW,
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND WALK-UPS."
I'VE NEVER HAD FOOD
LIKE THIS BEFORE,
BUT IT'S REALLY TASTY.
IT'S REALLY AUTHENTIC.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
HAS BEEN SOMETHING
I'VE EITHER EATEN
OR EATEN AND COOKED
IN ANOTHER COUNTRY
AND THEN BROUGHT IT BACK HERE.
(Guy)
TO SERVE UP TO ANDY RICKER'S
GROWING CROWD OF PORTLAND FANS.
WE OPENED AS JUST THIS SHACK
RIGHT HERE AND FROM THERE,
IT JUST GREW.
(Guy)
INTO THE HOUSE NEXT DOOR
AND A BARBECUE PIT IN THE BACK.
TO KEEP THAT FIRE HOT,
I'VE BEEN DOING MY BEST
TO GET PEOPLE TO TRY
SOMETHING NEW AND DIFFERENT.
(Guy)
YEP, BOAR MEAT, MARINATED,
GRILLED, SERVED WITH
CHILE LIME GARLIC SAUCE.
THEY SAID IT WAS
THE SPICIEST THING ON THE MENU,
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
WE'RE MAKING MUU PAA KHAM WAAN,
WHICH IS BOAR COLLAR,
THE NECK MEAT FROM THE BOAR.
WHY THE NECK?
IT'S GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR,
AND THE THAI PEOPLE REALLY
LIKE IT AS A CUT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE PASTE
THAT YOU RUB IT WITH.
THIS MORTAR AND PESTLE, THIS
GRANITE COMES FROM THAILAND.
WE'RE DOING CILANTRO ROOT,
GARLIC, LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
NOW WHY NOT A FOOD PROCESSOR?
THERE'S SOMETHING THAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU POUND IT
THAN IF YOU CUT IT.
IT'S REALLY THE TRADITIONAL WAY
OF DOING THINGS IN THAILAND.
NOW WE'RE JUST GOING TO TAKE
THIS PASTE
AND JUST KINDA WORK IT
INTO THE MEAT.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE SEASONING SAUCE
WHICH IS ESSENTIALLY
SOY SAUCE.
BUT LIGHTER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE
BIT OF SUPER FINE SUGAR.
BREAKS DOWN QUICKLY
AND EVENLY.
TYPICALLY, WE LET IT
MARINATE FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS
BEFORE WE GRILL IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SAUCE.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
TAKE THE CHILES, GARLIC,
DUMP 'EM IN THE ROBOT COUPE,
KINDA SET UP A LITTLE BIT.
SO IT'S NOT COMPLETELY
BROKEN DOWN, BUT WE GOT THOSE
FLAVORS COMBINING.
THEN THE LIME JUICE.
A LITTLE BIT OF ORANGE JUICE,
FISH SAUCE, AND THE SUGAR.
THIS IS TO COUNTERBALANCE?
IT BALANCES OUT
SOUR AND SALTY.
FINALLY, THE CILANTRO.
SO THIS HAS ALL THE THAI
HOT, SOUR, SALTY, SWEET.
AWESOME.
NOW IT'S GONNA GO ON THE GRILL.
REGULAR OLD CHARCOAL?
NATURAL HARDWOOD CHARCOAL.
WHAT DO YOU DO WHEN IT
RAINS HEAVY OUT HERE, GET WET?
WE JUST GET WET,
IT'S OREGON, MAN.
HOW WE LOOKIN'?
WE SHOULD BE AROUND MEDIUM,
MEDIUM RARE THERE.
PULL THAT OFF.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
SLICE IT UP,
PILE IT ON THE PLATE,
AND WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH THE SAUCE,
A LITTLE BIT OF CILANTRO FOR IT.
THEN WE GOT THE ICED
MUSTARD GREENS.
YOU TAKE A LITTLE STICKY RICE,
AND THEN YOU CAN USE THAT
TO PICK UP SOME OF THE MEAT
AND THE SAUCE AND POP THAT
IN YOUR MOUTH.
JUST TAKE A LITTLE NICE CRISPY
YU CHOY TO EAT WITH IT.
THIS IS RIDICULOUSLY GOOD,
CRUNCHY, SPICY, SUGAR, SALTY.
NORTHERN THAI DRINKING FOOD.
LOOKS GOOD, HUH,
HUNGRY CAMERA?
NOPE, NOT TODAY.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
SALTY, SPICY, JUST RIGHT.
SUPER AUTHENTIC, NOTHING THAT
YOU WOULD JUST FIND ANYWHERE.
O.T., ORIGINAL THAILAND.
(Guy)
RIGHT DOWN TO THE HARDWARE.
THIS IS A COCONUT MILK PRESS
THAT I BROUGHT BACK
FROM THAILAND.
WE'RE PUTTING IN
THE FRESH GRATED COCONUT,
MIXING WITH WARM WATER.
THERE'S A FILTER AND IT
PRESSES OUT THE COCONUT MILK.
(Guy)
ALL FOR ONLY ONE DISH,
THE COCONUT CURRY SOUP.
TOTALLY AUTHENTIC,
THAT'S THE WAY WE HAD IT
IN THE NORTHERN PART
OF THAILAND.
WE ALSO LIKE
THE KUUNG OP WUN SEN,
THE PORK BELLY AND THE PRAWNS.
HE'S GOING RIGHT
FOR THE PORK BELLY.
WELL, I MEAN, COME ON,
THAT'S CRAZY.
THE FLAVORS ARE SO INTENSE
BUT NOT SPICY.
NOT ALL THAI FOOD IS SPICY.
EXCELLENT DISH, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
THE FOOD'S DEFINITELY
DELICIOUS.
IT WAS WORTH THE WAIT
TO GET IN HERE TONIGHT.
(Guy)
OR YOU COULD JUST HEAD
TO THE TAKE-OUT WINDOW.
WE STARTED OUT WITH JUST
THIS MENU THAT'S RIGHT HERE.
THAT WAS IT,
A HANDFUL OF ITEMS,
(Guy)
INCLUDING THE ONE
THIS JOINT'S NAMED AFTER.
GREEN PAPAYA SALAD
OR PAPAYA POK POK.
POK POK'S AN ONOMATOPOEIA
THIS NOISE RIGHT HERE.
START OUT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
A COUPLE OF CHILES,
YOU LIKE IT SPICY?
I'LL TAKE MINE SPICY.
WE'LL MAKE IT THREE CHILES,
NICE BIG SCOOP OF PALM SUGAR.
THEN WE'RE GONNA START
POUNDIN' THAT DOWN.
THAT'S POK POK?
THAT'S POK POK.
NEXT WILL BE FRESH LIMES
WITH THE SKIN AND JUICE.
GARLIC, LIME,
AND CHILE MOJITO GOING.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT.
DRIED SHRIMP,
THEN I'M GONNA FOLLOW THAT
WITH SOME LONG BEANS.
THEN SOME LIME JUICE,
UBIQUITOUS FISH SAUCE.
THIS IS TAMARIND WATER
THAT HAS A NICE SOUR,
FRUITY FLAVOR TO IT.
NOW THE GREEN PAPAYA.
IT'S ALL GRATED FRESH
EACH TIME?
GRATED FRESH.
WE'RE GONNA START POUNDING IT
ALL TOGETHER HERE.
THE DRESSING GETS KINDA
PUSHED INTO THE GREEN PAPAYA,
BUT THE GREEN PAPAYA
STAYS NICE AND CRUNCHY.
NICE HANDFUL OF CHERRY TOMATOES
AND ADD SOME PEANUTS.
AND EACH TIME
THIS IS THE ROUTINE?
THIS IS THE WAY WE DO IT
EVERY TIME.
MAN, SOMEONE'S GONNA BE
WORKIN' HARD IN THIS JOB.
THE NEXT THING WE'LL DO
IS PLATE IT UP.
THEN YOU GOTTA EAT THIS
WITH STICKY RICE.
MMM, WOW, YOU GET
ALL THE FLAVORS, THE CRUNCH,
THE PRESENTATION.
EVERYBODY'S PLAYING NICE-NICE,
THERE'S NO LEAD GUITAR IN THIS.
THIS EMBODIES THE IDEA
OF HOT, SOUR, SALTY, SWEET
MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE.
MMM, AWESOME DUDE,
REALLY AWESOME.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT BLEND
OF SPICY AND SOUR.
IT'S REALLY TANGY.
THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE
DISHES, IT'S REAL EXQUISITE.
EVERYTHING IS SO
UNIQUELY DIFFERENT.
IT'S NOT JUST FROM ONE REGION.
OR ONE COUNTRY.
(Guy)
THE BIGGEST HIT ON THIS MENU
IS VIETNAMESE.
VIETNAMESE CHICKEN WINGS.
MY FRIENDS AND I
LIKE TO CALL IT MEAT CANDY.
THIS IS THE WING COCKPIT.
THIS IS THE WING COCKPIT
AT POK POK.
WHEN WE GET BACK,
YOU GET TO SEE THESE WINGS.
I HEAR THEY'RE OFF THE HOOK!
AT POK POK IN
PORTLAND, OREGON...
ANDY RICKER'S COOKING UP
FAVORITES HE BROUGHT HOME
FROM HIS TRAVELS ACROSS ASIA.
UNIQUE FOOD
THAT'S REALLY TASTY.
ECLECTIC BLEND OF THAI,
VIETNAMESE,
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
(Guy)
LIKE NORTHERN THAI
CURRY NOODLE SOUP.
THE FLAVORS ARE JUST AMAZING.
(Guy)
CHINESE WHOLE FRIED FISH.
IT SEALS ALL THE FLAVORS,
AND IT'S VERY TENDER.
(Guy)
AND CHICKEN WINGS
FROM VIETNAM.
THESE WINGS ARE AMAZING,
SPICY IS THE WAY
I LIVE MY LIFE.
IT AIN'T A THING
BUT A CHICKEN WING.
THAT'S RIGHT, WE'VE GOT
SOME CHOPPED GARLIC,
SOME SALT,
KINDA MASSAGE THAT TOGETHER
AND PULL THE LIQUID
OUT OF THE GARLIC.
ADD SOME WATER TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA USE CHEESECLOTH,
POUR THAT IN THERE
AND SQUEEZE IT.
THAT'LL FLAVOR THE WINGS
WITHOUT PUTTING GARLIC
ON THE WINGS.
BECAUSE IT'LL BURN...
IT'LL BURN WHEN YOU FRY IT.
TO THIS WE'RE GONNA ADD SUGAR...
SUPER FINE.
AND FISH SAUCE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MIX THAT ALL.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
THROW THAT MARINADE
ON THE CHICKEN WINGS,
GIVE IT A DARN GOOD MIXING.
YOU GOT NOT JUST
A MARINATION GOING,
YOU GOT A LITTLE OSMOSIS GOING.
WE GOT A BRINE GOING.
HOW LONG WILL THESE MARINATE?
OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE DEEP FRY 'EM?
YEAH, AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
TOSS 'EM IN THE WING CARAMEL
WHICH IS FISH SAUCE
AND GOOD CLEAN OREGON
TAP WATER
AND A WHOLE BUNCH OF SUGAR,
REAL SIMPLE.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S ALL MIXED.
NOW, WINGS, DRAINED 'EM,
DRIED 'EM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX
THE WING DUST WE CALL IT.
PLAIN OLD THAI
JASMINE RICE FLOUR.
THE RICE FLOUR IS SO SUPER FINE
THAT IT DOESN'T CLUMP UP ON IT.
THAT'S RIGHT, AND THEN
WE GOT TEMPURA MIX.
WE'RE GONNA GET SOME WINGS
IN THERE AND MIX THAT
ALL TOGETHER.
THIS IS FUNNY,
BECAUSE I'M NOT TYPICALLY
A FAN OF THE DREDGED WING,
BUT SINCE IT'S SUCH
A FINE FLOUR, I'LL TRY IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DROP IT
RIGHT IN THE DEEP FRYER.
WE'RE GONNA START HEATING
THAT CARAMEL BASE.
WHEN IT STARTS BUBBLING
WHEN IT'S SPICY...
YEAH, THROW A LITTLE HEAT
ON IT.
SOME OF THIS CHILE PASTE HERE,
THAT'S GONNA GIVE IT
THAT NICE TOASTY SPICED FLAVOR.
PULL THOSE WINGS OUT
AND YOU TOSS IT RIGHT IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IN
OUR FRIED GARLIC.
WOW, YOU CAN SEE THAT CANDY
RIGHT ON THERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA DO
A LITTLE TRICK HERE.
SPRITZ A LITTLE,
JUST THE TOUCH OF WATER,
PULLS THE STUFF
OFF THE SIDE OF THE PAN.
SEE, NICE GLAZE,
LET THOSE COOL A LITTLE BIT.
COOL LETTUCE TO GO
WITH THE HOT SPICY WINGS.
HOT, SPICY,
YOU GET THAT PART?
PICKLED DAIKON AND CUCUMBERS,
CARROTS, CILANTRO
TO CRUNCH UP WITH IT.
COOL DOWN.
MMM, LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHIN'.
THAT SAUCE ON THE OUTSIDE
OF THAT,
WITH THAT TEMPURA FLOUR,
MAKES IT.
CRUNCHY, TENDER, FALLS OFF
THE BONE, WHAT A DISH!
THEY JUST NEVER DISAPPOINT.
THEY'RE REALLY SWEET
AND CRISPY AND CARAMELIZED.
I GET THE WINGS EVERY TIME.
HOW MANY OF THESE HAVE YOU
PUT AWAY IN YOUR LIFETIME?
PROBABLY MORE THAN
YOU'VE HAD HOT MEALS.
ONE OF THE BEST MEALS
IN TOWN.
IT'S JUST VERY DIFFERENT.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND
PAD THAI HERE.
WE DON'T SELL PAD THAI AT ALL.
GIVE ME SOME.
NO PAD THAI.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GOING GANGSTER
WHEN YOU DON'T TAKE
THE SIGNATURE ITEM
OF THE TYPE OF FOOD
AND PUT IT ON YOUR MENU.
AH, THAT'S LEGIT, DUDE!
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
I'M HERE IN PORTLAND, OREGON.
(dog barking)