HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHEN I GOT IT,
IT WAS 80 YEARS OLD.
BLASTS FROM THE PAST.
CIRCA 1940.
IN LOS ANGELES...
HANGOVER HELPER.
ONE OF THE BEST
DINERS IN L.A.
A 70-YEAR-OLD CLASSIC...
A LOVELY SURPRISE.
WHERE COMFORT FOOD...
CATFISH IS UP.
MEETS CATFISH ON CORN CAKES...
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
AND DONUTS
WITH A DIFFERENCE.
BACON DONUTS!
IN BOSTON,
A SANDWICH JOINT...
WE GOT ANOTHER
ROAST BEEF.
THAT'S BEEN IN THE FAMILY
FOR MORE THAN 40 YEARS.
IT'S THE PERSONAL TOUCH HERE.
THIS IS SOMETHING SPECIAL.
AND, HEY...
WE LOVE OUR
CLAM CHOWDER.
BOSTON DOES MEAN SEAFOOD.
BIG CLAM FLAVOR.
MAKING YOUR OWN BROTH...
YEP.
IS THE REAL KICKER
RIGHT HERE.
AND IN OKLAHOMA CITY...
FINEST STEAKS YOU CAN GET
IN THE COUNTRY.
A 99-YEAR-OLD STEAKHOUSE...
PEPPERCORN STEAK, SIR.
ACROSS FROM THE STOCKYARDS,
WHERE COWBOY COOKIN'...
OH!
MEANS BRAINS AND EGGS.
MIND OVER MATTER, RIGHT?
I'M GONNA DO IT!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN THE HISTORIC CORE
OF LOS ANGELES
BY 5th AND MAIN--AN AREA
THEY USED TO CALL THE NICKEL.
NOW I'M GONNA VISIT A PLACE
THAT'S DOING SOME
DINER FAVORITES,
BUT WITH, YOU KNOW,
CALIFORNIA FLAIR.
IT'S THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU CAN REALLY FIND YOURSELF.
TIME TO CHECK OUT
NICKEL DINER.
TOFU SCRAMBLE...
THIS IS ONE OF A KIND.
HANGOVER HELPER.
THIS IS ONE OF A KIND,
NO MATTER WHERE YOU GO.
YEAH.
YOU THINK?
MERINGUE ON MANNEQUINS...
UPSIDE DOWN FLOOR LAMPS.
NO.
DONUTS SMOTHERED
IN BACON...
A LOVELY SURPRISE.
DONUTS WITH BACON!
EVERYBODY'S
LOOKING FOR A SURPRISE,
AND EVERYBODY WANTS
A LITTLE JOURNEY.
ESPECIALLY WHEN MONICA MAY
IS DOING THE DRIVING.
CATFISH IS UP.
AFTER 17 YEARS
IN THE FOOD BIZ,
SHE DECIDED
TO OPEN HER OWN JOINT
WITH HER PAL
KRISTEN TRATTNER.
THE DESSERTS--
ALL MADE HERE.
WE FOUND THIS PLACE.
IT WAS AN ABANDONED RESTAURANT.
IT LOOKS LIKE IT'S
FROM CIRCA 1940.
IT IS.
AND NOW THEY'RE MAKING
DINER FOOD...
THIS IS TOFU.
THEIR WAY.
SMAC AND CHEESE?
MAC AND CHEESE WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
CATFISH.
LOVE THE CATFISH.
HANDS DOWN.
CATFISH THAT'S ON CORN CAKES...
AND YOU'RE GONNA GET...
WITH BRUSSELS SPROUT HASH.
YES.
MM-HMM.
ARE YOU READY?
SO THIS IS OUR HOUSE
SPICE MIX.
IT'S GOT KOSHER SALT IN IT.
WE USE A LITTLE TURMERIC,
CUMIN--
SO YOU GET SOME NICE COLOR
OUT OF THE TURMERIC.
MMM.
ABSOLUTELY. MEXICAN CHILE
AND GUAJILLO CHILE.
OKAY, SO A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SPICE MIX,
AND ADD OTHER INGREDIENTS
TO MAKE THIS DRY RUB
FOR THE CATFISH?
YES, ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER,
DRIED THYME AND THEN
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
GONNA MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
WE HAVE THIS NICE
DRY RUB NOW.
THE CATFISH FILLETS,
DRY-RUBBED DOWN,
LET IT SET UP
A LITTLE BIT.
ABSOLUTELY.
PERMEATE SOME OF THE FLAVORS,
AND THEN THIS
IS GONNA GET PAN-FRIED?
PAN-FRIED.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
WHAT ARE WE ON TO NOW?
WE'RE MAKING CORN CAKES.
AND THIS IS FRESH CORN
THAT YOU CUT.
THIS IS FRESH CORN
RIGHT OFF THE COB.
OKAY.
PURéE THIS
IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR
TO GIVE US A NICE
OVERALL CORN FLAVOR.
SOME MINCED GREEN ONION,
AND WE'RE ADDING CHIVES.
WE'RE ALSO GOING TO ADD
REGULAR CORN FOR THE TEXTURE.
THEN WE'RE GOING
TO ADD THE HALF-AND-HALF,
MIX IT TOGETHER, THEN WE'RE
GOING TO DO OUR DRY INGREDIENTS.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, CORNMEAL...
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
MM-HMM. SUGAR, SALT.
ALL THAT, HUH?
BAKING POWDER
AND BLACK PEPPER.
IN NICKEL DINER LANGUAGE,
IS THAT STIRRING?
YES, IT IS.
I LIKE THAT.
AND THEN WE'RE
GOING TO DO SIX EGGS.
FLAVOR, COLOR AND BINDER
ALL THROUGH THE EGG.
MM-HMM.
GONNA ADD OUR DRY INGREDIENTS,
STIRRING IT UP.
SOME MELTED BUTTER.
BETTER WITH THE BUTTER.
OUR LAST INGREDIENT--
TABASCO.
AND THAT
IS OUR CORN CAKE BATTER.
ALL THAT EFFORT
JUST FOR ONE...
ALL THAT EFFORT.
SIDE PIECE TO GO
FOR THE CATFISH DINNER.
ABSOLUTELY.
JUST WHAT I EXPECTED
WHEN I DROVE UP.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE BRUSSELS SPROUT HASH.
START OFF WITH SOME
OLIVE OIL, BLANCHED BACON.
SHALLOTS. HERE COMES
OUR BLANCHED BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
OH, NICE SAVE.
GET THE REPLAY ON THAT.
SEE THE BRUSSELS SPROUT
COME OFF THE THING,
AND SHE NAILED IT
WITH THE PAN? THAT'S A PRO.
THERE YOU GO.
FRESH THYME.
CIDER VINEGAR.
OH, NICE LITTLE
BITE TO IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
GOT THE SWEETNESS
OF THE BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
A LITTLE SALT, FRESH RADICCHIO
FOR A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR.
COLOR AND ALSO A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT BITTERNESS.
FRESH PARSLEY.
PEPPER TO THE PAN.
SO WE HOLD THIS
OFF TO THE SIDE.
NOW WE START OUR FISH
AND OUR CAKES.
RIGHT.
SO A LITTLE OIL
IN THE PAN.
CATFISH THAT WE'VE
SEASONED.
HOT PAN, COLD OIL--
FOOD WON'T STICK.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
LOOKING FOR--
A NICE GOLDEN CRUST ON THERE.
GONNA POP IT IN THE OVEN.
OVEN'S AT 350. NOW WE'RE
INTO THE CORN CAKES.
GREAT CHUNKS
OF THE CORN IN THERE.
MAKE A BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE PANCAKE.
THANK YOU.
ONE, TWO.
HASH. BEAUTIFUL.
HERE'S OUR CATFISH.
WE'RE WORKING ON THE PAN SAUCE
RIGHT NOW.
WITH SHALLOTS, WHITE WINE
AND CANDIED PECANS.
HERE GOES.
I NEVER, NEVER WOULD
HAVE EXPECTED THAT.
BRUSSELS SPROUT HASH
WITH THE FRESH-BAKED CORN CAKE,
FRESH CATFISH THAT YOU'RE
DOING A CANDIED PECAN SAUCE
ON THE TOP OF. SISTER,
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
CATFISH--OFF THE HOOK.
REALLY GOOD.
MONICA DOES A GREAT JOB
OF MAKING
DIFFERENT VARIATIONS
OF DINER FOOD.
TOFU SCRAMBLE.
LIKE A CHICKEN SALAD SANDWICH
WITH FRESH BRINED CHICKEN
AND HOMEMADE
PICKLED ONIONS.
AWESOME.
THE KICKER, HANDS DOWN,
IS THE RED ONION.
(woman) PULLED PORK HASH,
5th AND MAIN.
THEIR DESSERTS ARE GREAT.
ALL MADE HERE,
ALL MADE FRESH.
AND ALL MADE BY REAL-DEAL
PASTRY CHEF SHARLENA FONG.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
HANDMADE POP TART.
YOU MAKE
DING DONG-LIKE DESSERT.
YEAH.
AND GET A LOAD
OF THIS ONE...
BACON DONUTS!
THERE YOU GO.
BACON ALWAYS MAKES
EVERYTHING BETTER.
ISN'T IT WEIRD WHEN YOU BITE
INTO DONUT TEXTURE
AND THEN YOU GET
CRUNCHY BACON TEXTURE?
I GUESS WE'LL
HAVE TO SEE.
FIRST WE START OFF
WITH SOME A.P. FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
DRY YEAST...
YES. ADD OUR EGGS.
THE ROCKY BALBOA
GATORADE.
SOME WHOLE MILK.
GIVE THAT A STIR.
THIS IS ALSO ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THIS ALLOWS THE YEAST
TO ACTIVATE.
MM-HMM.
CRACKS WILL FORM
IN THE FLOUR,
AND THIS WAY,
I KNOW IT'S READY TO GO.
AND THAT'S FROM
THE YEAST?
YES.
OH, SEE, THIS IS WHY
I DON'T BAKE.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE ADD FOUR, SALT
AND SUGAR MIXTURE.
AND NOW?
EGGS. NOW WE HAVE OUR HOOK.
CAPTAIN.
TURN THIS ON
FOR 15 MINUTES.
OKAY. ARE WE READY
TO MAKE DONUTS?
NOW WE HAVE TO ADD
ROOM TEMPERATURE BUTTER.
OKAY.
SIX MORE MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT RISE
FOR TWO HOURS,
AND THEN WE LET IT
SIT OVERNIGHT.
I KNOW, IT'S LONG.
FOR A DONUT?
SO THIS HAS RESTED
OVERNIGHT.
WE'VE GOT TO ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
GIVE THAT--I'LL SHOW YOU.
A LITTLE BIT MORE, YEAH.
(grunts)
HEY! AND NOW WE'VE GOT
TO ROLL THIS THING OUT. OKAY.
SMELLS GOOD.
SO NOW I'M GONNA
CUT OUT DONUTS.
WE CAN CUT OUT
THE HOLE AFTER.
THAT'S WHAT THIS SMALL
CUTTER IS FOR.
AHH.
SO WE CONTINUE TO PUNCH THESE
OUT, TAKE THE HOLES OUT OF 'EM,
LET 'EM RISE, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA FRY 'EM.
RIGHT.
HOW HOT'S THE OIL?
380.
380--DIG IT.
THE BAD BOYS ARE FRIED UP.
OUR GLAZE IS WITH
THE CONFECTIONERS' SUGAR
AND THE MAPLE SYRUP.
MM-HMM.
THE BACON--JUST REGULAR OLD
BACON THAT WE COOKED DOWN
AND CHOPPED UP.
STILL A LITTLE WARM.
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
BE ABLE TO WORK WITH THAT.
OKAY, SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
TAKE THE DONUT, DIP, DIP,
AND THEN GLAZE
THE WHOLE SIDE OF IT.
AND THEN WE DIP IT
IN THE BACON, AND THAT'S IT.
OH.
WOW, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT COULD BE DANGEROUS.
YOU SHOULD LIMIT PEOPLE TO
HOW MANY OF THOSE THEY CAN HAVE.
IT'S AS GOOD
AS YOU WOULD EXPECT.
PEOPLE ARE HAPPY,
THAT'S THE BEST PART.
BRILLIANCE.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
BACON BURGER.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
I AM BLOWN AWAY.
(both) THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
DID YOU WANT A PLATTER,
OR JUST A SANDWICH, SIR?
WE'RE HEADING TO BOSTON.
THE CHIPOTLE PASTRAMI.
FOR, YEAH--
A BASIC SANDWICH.
OH! YOU THINK IT'S BIG ENOUGH?
DELICIOUS SANDWICH.
I'M HERE IN DOWNTOWN BOSTON
TO VISIT A JOINT
THAT'S BEEN OWNED BY
THE SAME FAMILY SINCE '68.
NOW THEY'VE ALWAYS
BEEN SERVING SANDWICHES
IN ONE FORM OR ANOTHER, AND THEY
CONTINUE TO REINVENT THEMSELVES.
YOU KNOW, AS SANDWICH TRENDS
CHANGE, SO DOES THEIR NAME.
LET'S SEE, THEY STARTED
AS PROVIDENCE CAFETERIA,
THEN THEY WERE HUNGRY HORRORS,
THEN THEY WERE DOWNTOWN DELI,
THEN PROVIDENCE PLACE.
NOW SINCE '96 IT'S BEEN CALLED
SAM LaGRASSA'S,
WHERE THEY SAY THEY'RE SERVING
THE WORLD'S NUMBER 1 SANDWICHES.
GOT ANOTHER ROAST BEEF
GOING OVER THERE.
YOU GOT THE CORNED BEEF,
YOU GOT THE PASTRAMI.
THIS WAS ANOTHER THING
WE HAVE ON NEW YORK--
FIRST IN SANDWICHES,
FIRST IN BASEBALL.
CAN I HAVE
A CHICKEN PARM, PLEASE?
ANY SANDWICH YOU
ORDER HERE IS GREAT.
DID YOU WANT A PLATTER
OR THE SANDWICH, SIR?
I ACTUALLY ASKED SAM
IF HE WAS MARRIED, I SAID,
I'D HAVE MARRIED YOU
FOR YOUR PASTRAMI.
HE'S THE MICHELANGELO
OF SANDWICHES.
AND SAM LaGRASSA'S
BEEN MAKING MASTERPIECES
FOR MORE THAN 40 YEARS...
DAD, SET UP PORTOBELLO.
NOW WITH THE HELP
OF HIS THREE SONS.
THANK YOU, DONNA.
ROB, RONNIE, RICH.
FROM WHEN THEY WERE
ABLE TO WALK,
THIS BECAME JUST
A WAY OF LIFE.
THERE YOU GO.
ROB GOES OFF
TO CULINARY SCHOOL...
(speaking indistinctly)
YOU TWO TAKE OFF
AND GO WHERE?
BUSINESS SCHOOL.
HERE OR TO GO, SIR?
BUT THEY ALL CAME BACK
TO DAD'S PLACE.
EVERY DAY IS A NEW OPPORTUNITY
FOR A NEW SANDWICH.
WE'RE CONSTANTLY BUILDING,
CONSTANTLY PLAYING
WITH NEW STUFF.
LIKE THIS FAN FAVORITE.
CHIPOTLE PASTRAMI.
I LOVE CHIPOTLE AND COLESLAW,
AND IT HAS BOTH.
IT IS TRULY
JUST THE BEST.
START WITH SMOKED PASTRAMI,
DONE THEIR WAY...
WE TAKE THE STOCK
FROM THE PASTRAMIS
FROM THE DAY BEFORE,
ADD WATER TO IT...
WELL, YOU HAVE TO.
BECAUSE EVENTUALLY IT--
OTHERWISE,
IT WOULD BE SYRUP.
BEFORE WE PUT 'EM IN THE WATER
WE MAKE SURE WE SCORE 'EM.
YEAH.
THE STOCK IS BASICALLY
40 YEARS OLD.
SO YOU JUST KEEP
ROTATING THE STOCK.
AND THEN WE ADD
BROWN SUGAR.
AND THAT'S ALL THAT IS?
YEP.
SO HOW MANY HOURS?
TWO AND A HALF,
THREE HOURS.
READY?
GONNA LET IT COOL A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE WE SLICE IT?
NO, NEXT THING
WE'RE GONNA DO,
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE
BROWN SUGAR TO THE TOP OF IT.
OH, THAT'S JUST GONNA
MELT RIGHT IN THERE.
EXACTLY. IT REALLY GIVES IT
A NICE LITTLE SWEET TASTE.
THAT'S PSYCHO.
GOOD TO GO.
START SLICING IT UP.
THAT GUY WANTS YOU
OVER THERE...
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
THE BARK--SMOKE, PEPPER, SUGAR--
IN MY MOUTH.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA DO
THE CHIPOTLE HONEY MUSTARD.
START OFF WITH MUSTARD.
A LOT OF IT.
OH, YEAH. ADD THE HONEY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE BROWN SUGAR,
BROWN CHIPOTLE PEPPER, THEN
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
THAT SMELLS LIKE A SPICY
HONEY DIJON RIGHT NOW.
EXACTLY.
SO THIS YOU'RE GONNA
LET SET UP.
WHAT ELSE GOES
ON THE SANDWICH?
COLE SLAW--WE'RE GONNA
START WITH FRESH CABBAGE,
SHREDDED CARROTS, GRANULATED
SUGAR, WHITE VINEGAR.
NOT APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
HUH?
NOPE, THAT'S THE WAY
DAD ALWAYS MADE IT.
WE DON'T MESS WITH THAT.
KOSHER SALT,
FRESHLY GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
WHOLE CELERY SEED,
PARSLEY AND MAYONNAISE,
AND THEN WE MIX IT UP.
THIS SETS UP,
AND THEN YOU--
FINALLY WE'RE GONNA
HAVE PASTRAMI?
THEN WE'LL BUILD IT.
GOOD.
GRAB AN ITALIAN ROLL, START
WITH OUR CHIPOTLE HONEY MUSTARD,
SWISS CHEESE AND THE COLESLAW
WILL GO ON THE TOP PART.
HOLY--YOU THINK
IT'S BIG ENOUGH?
NOW WHERE
ARE YOU GOING?
NOW WE BRING IT
ONTO THE GRILL.
OKAY, SO HOW LONG
IS THIS ON THE PRESS.
A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
LOOK AT THAT. SO IS THIS
ONE OF YOUR FAVORITES?
OH, WITHOUT A DOUBT.
DELICIOUS SANDWICH.
TAKE A LOOK
AT HOW NICE AND CRISPY
AND CRUNCHY THAT BREAD'S BECOME.
LOOK AT THAT PASTRAMI.
THE SUGAR RUBDOWN YOU GAVE IT.
OKAY.
SLAW'S GOT GOOD TANG,
BUT THE KICKER--
THAT CHIPOTLE MUSTARD--
REALLY NICE HEAT. NOT OVERDONE.
I WAS WORRIED IT WAS GONNA
BE TOO MUCH OF THE FLAVOR.
THAT'S KILLER.
IT'S A LOT OF MEAT
IN ONE SHOT.
IT'S THE PERFECT
TYPE OF COLESLAW.
THE CHIPOTLE JUST REALLY
SETS IT OFF.
THIS IS YOUR GO-TO
FOR PASTRAMI?
PASTRAMI--ONLY PLACE
FOR ME FOR PASTRAMI.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
CORNED BEEF.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS FIRST CLASS.
FOR HERE OR TO GO, SIR?
THEY'VE GOT A HUGE
TAKEOUT OPERATION.
IT'S CRAZY. 40 PEOPLE DOWNSTAIRS
MAKING SANDWICHES.
SO YOU'RE DOING 1,300
SANDWICHES A DAY?
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S JUST IN CATERING.
IT'S EASILY THE BEST
SANDWICH SHOP IN BOSTON.
MMM.
SO OF COURSE A COUPLE
OF HUNDRED PEOPLE A DAY
COME IN FOR THIS.
WE LOVE
OUR CLAM CHOWDER.
HOW DOES THIS CLAM CHOWDER
STACK?
IT'S A-PLUS.
SO NO CANNED CLAMS
GOING INTO THIS?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
IT'S GOTTA BE OUT OF THE SHELL.
AND YOU GOTTA MAKE
YOUR OWN BROTH.
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK AT THOSE.
WHAT KIND OF CLAM IS THIS?
IT'S CALLED A QUAHOG,
FROM CAPE COD.
AND THEN EVERYBODY'S
GONNA STEAM?
YEP.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
START WITH SOME
FRESH CHOPPED ONIONS.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME DRIED
THYME, A COUPLE OF BAY LEAVES,
A FEW PEPPERCORNS, FRESH MINCED
GARLIC, FRESH-CHOPPED PARSLEY.
YOU'RE JUST MAKING
A NICE, LIGHT BROTH.
EXACTLY.
HOW MUCH WATER?
A COUPLE CUPS.
YOU WANT JUST ENOUGH
JUST TO STEAM
THE CLAMS OPEN.
PUT A LID ON IT. I'LL BUY
YOU A LID FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY.
WHAT'S GOING ON WITH THIS?
OLD SCHOOL.
LET THIS STEAM...
YEP.
FIVE MINUTES.
HOW THEY LOOKIN'?
ONCE THE SHELL'S OPEN,
THEY'RE GOOD TO GO.
AWESOME, SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS STRAIN OUT THE JUICE.
SO THAT'S THE BROTH
THAT'S GONNA GET USED
IN MAKING THE CHOWDER.
NOW YOU TAKE
THESE BAD BOYS--
WE'RE GONNA TAKE 'EM
OUT OF THE SHELL.
JUST CHOP 'EM UP. WE'RE GONNA
SLICE UP THE BACON.
MAD KNIFE SKILLS.
OKAY, THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD THAT TO THE POT.
NEXT THING WE'RE GONNA DO
IS ADD SOME ONIONS.
ONCE THOSE GET TRANSLUCENT,
WE'LL ADD THE LEAKS,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
CHOPPED CELERY.
FOR A LITTLE SWEETNESS.
EXACTLY. GONNA ADD
SOME BUTTER.
A LITTLE MORE FAT.
ADD SOME THYME,
FRESH MINCED GARLIC.
OH, I LIKE THAT CALL.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER
AND SOME SHALLOTS.
SO WE'LL LET
THIS ALL COOK DOWN.
GET ALL THOSE FLAVORS
TOGETHER.
IT SMELLS FANTASTIC.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD CHOPPED
YUKON GOLD POTATOES,
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE CLAM STOCK
THAT WE USED TO STEAM
THE CLAMS OPEN.
THAT'S PURE FLAVOR, BABY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE FRESH CHOPPED CLAMS.
SO THAT'S SIMMERED
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
HEAVY CREAM, TOUCH OF MILK.
SO IT DOESN'T HAVE--
THAT'S IT?
YEP.
THE BROTH IS THE FLAVOR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT--
KOSHER SALT,
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
FRESH-CHOPPED PARSLEY,
A LITTLE BIT OF CAYENNE PEPPER
AND SOME WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
PUT ALL MY FAVORITE
INGREDIENTS IN THERE.
THAT'S THE WAY WE DO IT.
WE DO IT OLD SCHOOL, REAL DEAL.
THIS IS HOW
YOUR DAD TAUGHT YOU?
THAT'S THE WAY.
I LOVE IT. CRACKERS
ALREADY COME ON IT, HUH?
PARSLEY.
OH. DELICIOUS.
BIG CLAM FLAVOR.
LOOK AT ALL THE CLAMS IN THERE.
TENDER POTATOES,
LITTLE NIBBLES OF BACON.
MAKING YOUR OWN BROTH I THINK
IS THE REAL KICKER RIGHT HERE.
YEP.
MMM.
TOP-NOTCH.
SEASONING IS JUST RIGHT.
IF I GET IT, I ONLY GET IT HERE.
REAL DEAL CHOWDER?
OH, YEAH, REAL DEAL.
REAL NEW ENGLAND STYLE.
JUST THE WAY WE LIKE IT.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
PASTRAMI. THANK YOU.
(man) IT'S THE PERSONAL
TOUCH HERE.
THIS IS SOMETHING SPECIAL.
(woman) THE WORLD'S
NUMBER ONE SANDWICH.
WE'VE NEVER BEEN
CHALLENGED YET.
A LITTLE MUSTARD...
TURKEY.
FOR ME, IT'S JUST CONSTANTLY
DRIVING ME EVERY SINGLE DAY,
EVERY SINGLE SANDWICH.
THAT'S A DUDE
THAT'S DEDICATED.
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT. THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, AND CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP--OKLAHOMA.
SMALL FILLET, MEDIUM.
EXCELLENT.
ONE OF THE BEST PEPPERCORN
STEAKS I'VE HAD.
DID SOMEONE SAY
BEEF COUNTRY?
WOW, THAT IS SMOKIN' HOT!
WHEN I WENT TO COLLEGE
AT THE UNIVERSITY OF NEVADA
LAS VEGAS,
I HAD VARIOUS JOBS IN A PLACE
CALLED SCHULMAN MEAT COMPANY.
SO, YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE "D" I
LOVE IT WHEN WE CAN FIND A PLACE
THAT'S SPECIALIZING
IN AGED HAND-CUT STEAKS
AND DOING IT
CLOSE TO 100 YEARS.
SO HERE I AM
IN A HISTORIC DISTRICT
OF OKLAHOMA CITY
CALLED STOCKYARD CITY
TO CHECK OUT THIS JOINT,
CATTLEMEN'S STEAKHOUSE.
PRESIDENTIAL T-BONE,
BEAUTIFUL.
IF YOU'RE FROM OKLAHOMA,
YOU GOTTA EAT BEEF...
TWO LUNCH STEAKS, MEDIUM.
I LOVE THE T-BONE.
PRIME RIB EYE...
SMALL FILLET, MEDIUM.
EXCELLENT.
ONE OF THE BEST PEPPERCORN
STEAKS I'VE HAD.
SINCE I WAS
A VERY YOUNG GIRL WITH MY DAD,
THIS WAS
THE PLACE TO COME.
GOES BACK EVEN FURTHER
THAN THAT--99 YEARS.
WHEN I GOT IT,
IT WAS 80 YEARS OLD.
THE LAST THING I WANTED TO DO
WAS FOR THE CUSTOMERS TO THINK
THAT WE CHANGED.
HOW'S THE FOOD TODAY?
VERY GOOD.
THEY'D RUN YOU OUT OF TOWN IF
YOU WENT AND PAINTED THIS THING.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
SO OWNER DICK STUBBS...
MMM, THAT'S REAL GOOD.
BROUGHT IN LONGTIME
RESTAURANT BUDDY DAVID EGAN...
SMALL FILLET,
HALFWAY ALONG.
TO KEEP THE PLACE
THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
EVERY STEAK
HAS GOTTA BE PERFECT.
THIS BAD BOY RIGHT HERE,
THIS IS A NEEDLING MACHINE?
WE WILL PUT EVERY PIECE OF MEAT
THROUGH THAT MACHINE.
SO THERE'S THOUSANDS
OF LITTLE NEEDLES THAT'S
PRESSED RIGHT THROUGH THAT.
THIS JUST ENSURES THAT
YOU BREAK A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT
CONNECTIVE TISSUE APART,
JUST MAKES IT
A LITTLE MORE TENDER.
SO THERE'S NO QUESTION
THAT EVERY STEAK
IS GONNA BE
PERFECTLY TENDER.
ALL 9,000
OF THEM EVERY WEEK.
NOW THIS
IS THE LOIN BONE-IN.
HOW MANY OF THESE
WILL YOU BREAK DOWN?
PROBABLY
ABOUT 20 OR 30.
A DAY?
YEAH.
AND THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE
GETTING THIS CLASSIC...
T-BONE. WE SOLD
120 LAST NIGHT.
AND I WASN'T EVEN HERE.
THAT'D BEEN 127.
THE T-BONE, I LOVE IT.
SO DID THE FIRST PRESIDENT BUSH
WHEN HE DROPPED BY.
THEY EVEN
NAMED IT AFTER HIM.
PRESIDENTIAL CHOICE,
GREAT STEAK.
SO IS THIS ONE--
A NEW YORK STRIP
AND TENDERLOIN ALL IN ONE.
IT'S THE PORTERHOUSE
SPECIAL.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT!
AND THEY'RE ALL SEASONED UP
THE CATTLEMEN'S WAY.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE HERE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
CATTLEMEN'S STEAK SEASONING.
THIS IS WHAT YOU SPRINKLE
ON THE STEAKS WHEN IT COOKS.
ON EVERY STEAK.
MUST MAKE THIS BY
THE 50,000-GALLON DRUM
EVERY DAY.
UH, VERY LARGE.
YEAH.
A LITTLE SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC, ONION SALT,
SEASONING SALT
AND BLACK PEPPER.
MAKE SURE IT'S MIXED UP
REAL GOOD. THAT'S IT.
MMM. PUT SOME MORE
OF THAT IN MY HAND.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
THROW IT ON THE GRILL.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
SEASONING, AND THAT WORKS
WITH THE FAT AND THE NATURAL
JUICES OF THE MEAT.
WOW, THAT
IS SMOKIN' HOT.
650 DEGREES.
THIS WILL TAKE
NINE, TEN MINUTES?
YEAH, ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
THAT'S
A GOOD-LOOKING STEAK, MAN.
FLIP IT.
I'M GONNA SEASON IT.
I THINK WE'RE READY TO GO.
STEAK FOR TEN.
A LITTLE AU JUS.
WE MAKE OUR AU JUS.
THERE WE GO,
READY FOR DINNER.
LOOK AT THAT.
SAY SOMETHING.
YOU DON'T NEED TO SAY ANYTHING.
IT SPEAKS FOR ITSELF.
SUPER TENDER,
THE GRILLING IS PERFECT.
THE AU JUS IS A NICE TOUCH.
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
TASTES LIKE THE MOST DELICATE
MOIST MEAT EVER.
ONE OF THE FINEST STEAKS
YOU CAN GET IN THE COUNTRY.
BASIC, BACON-WRAPPED, THEY'RE
EVEN DOING STEAK AU POIVRE.
I LIKE SPICE,
AND THIS IS PERFECT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME PEPPERCORN SAUCE.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH MAKING A ROUX--
A LITTLE BUTTER,
GONNA ADD A LITTLE FLOUR,
THEN WE'RE GONNA LET IT COOK
FOR ABOUT THREE OR FOUR MINUTES.
YOU GOTTA COOK OUT
THAT FLOUR TASTE.
TAKE THE BEEF AU JUS,
A LITTLE BRANDY.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE
GONNA ADD OUR ROUX.
THERE YOU GO,
THANK YOU, PAL.
SO THAT'LL
HELP TIGHTEN IT UP.
FRESH CRACKED PEPPER, LET
THAT COOK FOR A MINUTE OR TWO.
GET A LITTLE OF THAT BRANDY
COOKED OUT OF THERE.
NOW WHAT DO
WE GOT RIGHT HERE?
THAT'S A LITTLE
CULINARY CREAM.
CRèME FRAîCHE IS WHAT
PEOPLE WOULD KNOW IT AS.
WANT A HAND THERE, BROTHER?
THANK YOU.
LET IT REDUCE A LITTLE BIT MORE,
THEN WE'LL POP THAT ON THE SINK.
VERY GOOD.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
KNOCK IT OUT MEDIUM RARE?
THERE YOU GO. NOW FOR
THE SPECIAL SEASONING.
WE'RE JUST
GONNA TURN IT OVER.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT SEASONING ON THERE...
YEAH.
AND THAT'S IT.
SHE'S READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS AIN'T YOU FIRST STEAK.
SECOND.
READY FOR
THE PEPPERCORN SAUCE?
YEAH, HIT IT, HIT IT.
FEW LITTLE PEPPERCORNS,
READY FOR DINNER.
MMM, THAT'S KILLER.
THAT IS SO TENDER.
I'D DRINK
THAT PEPPERCORN SAUCE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THAT STEAK'S OFF THE HOOF.
NOT OFF
THE HOOK, HOOF.
PEPPER STEAK,
MEDIUM, COMIN' UP.
GREAT STEAK FLAVOR,
BUT THEN THE PEPPERCORN,
IT REALLY ADDS A LITTLE KICK.
GREAT STEAKS.
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM THE STOCKYARDS.
YOU UNLOADED YOUR CATTLE
AND THEN CAME HERE TO EAT.
IT REALLY CAPTURES
THE OKLAHOMA FRONTIER IMAGE.
IT'S OLD OKLAHOMA CITY.
WITH AN OLD OKLAHOMA MENU.
THE ONLY PLACE THAT I KNOW
OF IN THE STATE OF OKLAHOMA
THAT YOU CAN GET
BRAINS AND EGGS.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
A LITTLE BUTTER.
CALF BRAINS AND EGGS--
IS THAT A SPECIALTY?
IT'S JUST WHAT WE EAT FOR
BREAKFAST EVERY MORNING
HERE AT CATTLEMEN'S.
LET'S GET SOME BRAINS.
THIS IS NOT
GONNA BE GOOD FOR ME.
MAKE SURE THOSE BRAINS
ARE GOOD AND TENDER.
ADD THE SCRAMBLED EGGS,
LET IT SET UP FOR A MINUTE.
NOW WE'LL ADD
A LITTLE STEAK SEASONING.
MMM.
I DON'T LIKE EGGS,
AND I DON'T LIKE BRAINS.
I DEFINITELY DON'T LIKE
EGG AND BRAIN. OH, GOD.
I'M GONNA NEED TOAST
OR SOMETHING, BACON
TO CHOKE THIS DOWN.
OKAY, YOU READY?
GET A FORK.
SO THE YELLOW PART'S
THE CHICKEN,
AND THE BROWN PART
IS THE BRAIN MATTER.
THAT'S CORRECT.
IS IT GONNA
MAKE ME SMARTER?
THAT'S GUARANTEED
TO MAKE YOU SMARTER.
CAN I HAVE SOME SAUCE
OR SOMETHING?
THERE YOU GO.
MIND OVER MATTER, RIGHT?
GOD, I DON'T WANT TO DO IT!
HEY!
OH, GOD.
ARE YOU
GETTING READY TO--OH.
OH!
THAT'S A LAMB FRY.
OH, AWESOME.
BREADED LAMB TESTICLES.
GOT A LAMB DINNER
IN THE WINDOW!
I DON'T KNOW
WHO CAME UP WITH IT,
BUT WHOEVER DID
HAD A GREAT IDEA.
THEY'RE EXCELLENT.
THEY KINDA TASTE LIKE
FRIED CLAMS OR OYSTERS.
IT TASTES LIKE CHICKEN.
WE ALWAYS GET
'EM WHEN WE COME HERE.
JUST KINDA A TRADITION.
SO IS THIS.
EVER SINCE
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE,
I ALWAYS
HAVE HOUSE DRESSING.
THAT'S RIGHT,
FOLKS HAVE BEEN COMING BACK
YEAR AFTER YEAR
FOR A SALAD DRESSING...
EXCELLENT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
LUNCH STEAK,
MEDIUM WELL.
AT CATTLEMEN'S STEAKHOUSE
AT OKLAHOMA CITY...
THAT'S MEDIUM.
DAVID EGAN
AND DICK STUBBS...
YEAH.
ARE KEEPING THINGS THE WAY
THEY'VE ALWAYS BEEN...
THANK YOU.
FROM THE STEAKS...
FANTASTIC.
TO THE COCONUT CREAM PIE...
IT'S EXCELLENT.
TO THE SALAD DRESSING...
CATTLEMEN'S
SPECIAL HOUSE DRESSING.
FOLKS HERE
HAVE BEEN LOVING FOR DECADES.
JUST OUTSTANDING.
HOUSE DRESSING.
WHAT'S IN IT?
DAVID'LL NEVER TELL ME.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHEN WE BOUGHT THE RESTAURANT
FROM THE PREVIOUS OWNER,
HE OPENED UP HIS WALLET
AND PULLED OUT A LITTLE
PIECE OF PAPER, AND THAT
WAS THE HOUSE DRESSING RECIPE.
HE HAD IT FOR 45 YEARS,
AND THEN HE PASSED IT ON TO US.
WHO MAKES THE DRESSING?
ROSIE. SHE WON'T
GIVE YOU THE RECIPE,
BUT SHE'LL SHOW YOU
HOW SHE MAKES IT.
YOU JUST MAKE IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
DON'T TALK TO ME
ABOUT ANY OF THE DETAILS.
I DON'T TALK
ABOUT ANYTHING ELSE.
OKAY,
LET'S GET IT GOING.
EGGS...
OHH.
WHOO-HOO. LOOKS LIKE WE'RE
MAKING CHICKEN COTTON CANDY.
THIS IS THE OIL, HALF
COTTONSEED AND HALF GARLIC.
HAVE GARLIC OIL?
YEAH.
WHOO-HOO! IT'S GETTIN'
MAYONNAISE-Y IN THERE, AIN'T IT?
YES, WHITE PEPPER.
WHAT IS THIS ONE?
COTTONSEED OIL,
MUSTARD FLOUR.
MORE GARLIC OIL?
YES.
WHOA, NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
THAT IS GARLIC OIL.
WE MARINATE IT
FOR 16 DAYS.
THE OIL.
YEP. YES.
ALL THE GARLIC
GETS CHOPPED UP,
PUT IN THE CHEESE CLOTH...
RIGHT.
AND IT SITS
IN THERE FOR 16 DAYS?
RIGHT, MM-HMM.
ALL THIS IS JUST TO MAKE
THE SPECIAL DRESSING?
YES.
THAT'S DRESSING DEDICATION
101, HUH?
OKAY.
NOW WHAT
ARE WE GONNA DO?
SO REGULAR MILK.
MORE OIL?
IS THAT COTTONSEED?
YEAH. HALF AND HALF.
VINEGAR.
WHITE VINEGAR...
(whistles)
LEMON JUICE.
THE WHOLE THING?
THAT'S JUST A QUART TO GO
WITH ALL THIS--ALL OF IT.
SO HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA GO?
PROBABLY ABOUT
THREE MINUTES.
REAL GOOD.
WHEN THIS IS BROKEN,
DO YOU DO IT BY HAND?
NO, WE GET IT FIXED.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YEAH, AND QUICKLY. THERE'D BE
A STAMPEDE, NO PUN INTENDED...
RIGHT.
IF WE DON'T
HAVE THIS DRESSING.
SCRAPE IT DOWN
WITH MY SPATULA.
NOW WE PUT THE CHEESE IN.
CHEDDAR?
CHEDDAR CHEESE, YES.
OKAY.
HOW LONG DOES THIS GO?
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
CHEESE GOTTA MIX
REAL GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TASTE IT?
RIGHT.
THAT'S CRAZY. YOU DEFINITELY
PICK UP THE GARLIC.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I DIG ABOUT IT--
CHUNKS OF CHEESE,
THAT'S THE KEY.
SO SALAD
COMES WITH EVERYTHING?
EVERY DISH.
MMM, THAT DRESSING
IS ADDICTING.
CREAMY LIKE
A GARLICKY RANCH DRESSING
BUT NOT AS HERBACEOUS.
AWESOME, MAN.
HERE'S YOUR SALAD
WITH THE HOUSE DRESSING.
JUST HAS A GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
I DO LIKE IT.
HERE'S YOUR STEAK, MA'AM.
CATTLEMEN'S IS BASICALLY
LIKE IT WAS 50, 60 YEARS AGO.
(man) AU JUS.
VERY GOOD FLAVOR.
IT'S ALWAYS REALLY GOOD.
I UNDERSTAND WHY YOU GUYS
HAVE BEEN HERE 100 YEARS.
WELL...
NICE JOB.
WE'RE SHOOTIN'
FOR ANOTHER 100.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA HAVE ANY
PROBLEM WITH THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WAS THAT
A KILLER ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
DON'T WORRY--WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS ALL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'LL SPLIT IT WITH YOU.
DON'T TELL. SHH.
HOW WAS THAT?
HEY, WHAT'S UP?
(man) DONE?
SMOOTH, HUH?