HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
I NEED THE MASHWI SHISH.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
CARNITAS.
SWEDISH MEATBALLS.
GLOBAL GRUB--
SCANDINAVIAN...
SWEDISH PANCAKES.
IN CHICAGO.
OKAY, HERE COMES THE DUCK.
WHAT THIS COUPLE GREW UP WITH.
THESE ARE AEBLESKIVERS.
OH, THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
GRAVLAX APPETIZER.
THEY MAKE IT GOOD.
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA...
(speaking Spanish)
HUARACHE.
THE MEXICAN PLACE...
HOW IS IT, MOM?
YUM, DELICIOUS.
WHERE I'VE BEEN BRINGING
MY FAMILY FOR YEARS.
REAL AS IT GETS.
CAN YOU SAY "AUTHENTIC"?
PIG'S FEET.
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY
THAT YOU GET OFFERED THAT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND IN NORTH ARLINGTON, TEXAS,
WHAT ELSE?
TWO FALAFELS,
TWO TABBOULEH, READY TO GO.
CLASSIC LEBANESE...
WHEN YOU'VE GOT THE NEED,
THE NEED FOR LEBANESE...
THIS IS WHERE YOU GO.
AT WHAT USED TO BE
A CLASSIC DRIVE-IN.
HOW WE DOIN'?
WE'RE DOIN' WELL.
SOME HANDMADE DELICIOUS PILAF.
YOU GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP
RIGHT HERE ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE
ON THE NORTHWEST SIDE OF CHICAGO
AT A PLACE WHOSE BUILDING
WAS BUILT IN 1896.
NOW IT'S RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM A SCANDINAVIAN COLLEGE,
AND IN A PREDOMINANTLY
SCANDINAVIAN NEIGHBORHOOD,
AND THIS PLACE IS OWNED
BY A FIRST-
AND SECOND-GENERATION
SCANDINAVIAN COUPLE.
NOW GUESS
WHAT KIND OF CUISINE THEY COOK?
YOU GOT IT--CHINESE. NO.
SERIOUSLY, IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR SOME DYNAMITE DANISH,
SWEDISH AND NORWEGIAN FOOD,
YOU GOTTA COME CHECK OUT
TRE KRONOR.
TWO SWEDISH MEATBALLS.
SWEDISH MEATBALLS,
PICKLED HERRING--
A BIG SMORGASBORD.
YEAH.
SWEDISH PANCAKES.
I'M FROM A SWEDISH FAMILY,
SO IF YOU WANNA GO HOME
AND GET SOMETHING TO EAT,
IT'S LIKE, JUST COME HERE.
AT THIS JOINT LARRY ANDERSON
AND HIS WIFE PATTY...
HOW YOU DOIN'?
BOUGHT ON A WHIM
17 YEARS AGO.
I WAS A SWEDISH WAITER...
(man) FALUKORV SAUSAGE.
SHE WAS A NORWEGIAN WAITRESS.
RICE PUDDING.
WE JUST THOUGHT, LET'S DO
THE STUFF THAT WE LIKE,
AND WE'LL LEARN
AS WE GO.
FROM NEW TWISTS
ON TRADITIONAL RECIPES...
MEATBALL SANDWICH.
TO A SCANDINAVIAN CLASSIC.
INGRID, I'VE GOT
YOUR GRAVLAX FOR YOU.
SALMON FLAVORED WITH AQUAVIT,
AN 80-PROOF SWEDISH FAVORITE.
I KNOW HOW TO MAKE GRAVLAX.
THEY MAKE IT GOOD.
LAX MEAN "SALMON"
IN SWEDISH.
OH! SEE?
OKAY, SO GRAV
MEANS "GRAVE,"
'CAUSE THE TRADITIONAL WAY
OF DOING THIS
WAS YOU MADE THIS,
AND YOU BURIED IT UNDERGROUND.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
WE START WITH THE TWO SALMON.
POUR A LITTLE AQUAVIT...
SO YOU DO A SHOT OF THAT?
ONE FOR THE CHEF,
ONE FOR THE SALMON, YEAH.
I LIKE IT.
THEN I LIKE TO RUB
IT IN A LITTLE BIT,
MASSAGE IT, SPANK IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CURING MIX,
AND I DO 3-2,
SUGAR TO SALT.
AND A LITTLE PEPPER.
MIX THAT ALL UP.
AND THEN
WE TOTALLY COVER IT.
IT'S LIBERAL.
YEAH, THE SALT
DOES THE WORK.
AND THAT'S PULLING OUT
THE MOISTURE.
YEAH, AND THEN A LOT OF DILL.
FLIP THIS PIECE ON.
AND I'M GONNA PUT
THE REST OF THE SALT MIXTURE
RIGHT ON TOP
OF THE SKIN OF THIS.
WRAP THAT UP IN PLASTIC.
WE'LL STICK IT IN THE FRIDGE.
HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS CURE?
THREE DAYS IS PERFECT.
THIS IS SOME GRAVLAX
THAT WE MADE YESTERDAY.
YOU CAN SEE THE JUICES
ALREADY CAME OUT.
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK AT
THE TEXTURE OF THE MEAT.
IT'S ALREADY STARTING
TO GET A LITTLE BIT HARD.
MM-HMM.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA
BASTE IT OVER THE TOP?
BASTE IT, AND WE'RE GONNA
FLIP IT, WRAP IT UP AGAIN.
SO THAT'LL GO ANOTHER DAY,
AND THEN WE'RE READY TO SERVE?
YEP.
(imitating Sean Connery)
AYE, CAPTAIN,
YOU WANT ME TO TAKE THIS--
(normal voice)
I'M SORRY. OH, YOU'RE BACK.
THIS WE MADE
TWO DAYS AGO.
ALL THE JUICE IS OUT OF IT.
IT'S ALMOST LEATHERY.
LOOK AT THAT.
SCRAPE OFF ALL THE DILL.
THAT DILL SMELLS AWESOME.
WE'RE JUST GONNA CUT SOME
PRETTY THIN SLICES HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
GRAVLAX MADE FRESH--
JUST WHERE YOU EXPECT
TO FIND IT--IN CHICAGO.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE IT WITH
SOME DILL CREAM POTATOES,
A LEMON,
A LITTLE SPRIG OF DILL,
A LITTLE WASA BREAD.
PILE THAT UP ON TOP.
MMM. DELICATE TEXTURE.
I MEAN, IT JUST MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
NOT SALTY,
NOT OVER DILL--MMM.
I LIKE THE CONTRAST OF THE COOL
SALMON, WARM POTATO SALAD.
WE SERVE A LOT
IN THE SUMMERTIME.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
PEOPLE LOVE IT.
WAY TO ROCK THAT OUT.
GRAVLAX APPETIZER.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
I REALLY LIKE IT.
TELL ME
WHAT'S SO GOOD ABOUT IT.
IT'S TRADITIONAL.
GOT A LITTLE SWEDISH
FLAVOR TO IT.
IS THIS THE KIND OF FOOD
YOU GREW UP EATING?
IT ACTUALLY IS.
OKAY, HERE COMES
THE PANCAKES.
COD MEATBALLS?
COD MEATBALLS.
RAINBOW TROUT
WITH BUTTER SAUCE.
WHAT'S REALLY MADE
THE RESTAURANT TAKE OFF
IS A LITTLE TASTE
OF REAL SCANDINAVIA,
AND WE STARTED
MAKING IT IMPERATIVE
THAT WE'D GO EVERY YEAR
AND BRING BACK
ALL SORTS OF RECIPES.
HERE WE ARE.
DUCK BREAST.
I THINK I HAVE TRIED EVERYTHING
THEY HAVE ON THE MENU.
FROM PASTRIES
LIKE AEBLESKIVER...
AEBLESKIVER MEANS
"APPLE PANCAKES."
SORT OF A DANISH SPECIALTY.
DELICIOUS.
GRANDMOTHER WOULD BE PROUD TO
SEE THAT THIS IS STILL ROLLIN'.
I THINK SHE WOULD.
TO SCANDINAVIAN STAPLES
LIKE PICKLED HERRING--
DONE TEN DIFFERENT WAYS.
MAN, I'M TELLING YOU,
THE ONE WITH THE BASIL--
THAT'S DELICIOUS.
AND OF COURSE...
TWO MEATBALLS.
THIS SCANDINAVIAN CLASSIC.
IF SHE MAKES THE MENU,
IT'S "NORWEGIAN MEATBALLS."
WE HAVE THIS SPAT.
WHEN I DO IT,
IT'S SWEDISH MEATBALLS.
EITHER WAY,
THEY'RE PUTTING IT TOGETHER
JUST LIKE
PATTY'S GRANDMOTHER DID.
YEAH, WITH THE LINGON.
LINGONBERRY.
WITH THE LINGON.
YEAH, YEAH.
SWEDISH MEATBALLS.
THEY'RE CALLED KOTTBULLAR.
KOTTBULLAR.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME BREAD CRUMBS,
ADD SOME HALF-AND-HALF.
THAT WHOLE QUART
OF HALF-AND-HALF.
GONNA INCORPORATE
THE SALT INTO THIS?
YEAH,
AND I PUT THE PEPPER IN
AND ADD A LITTLE NUTMEG.
THAT'S OUR SECRET INGREDIENT.
I JUST TOLD YOU IT.
YOU DIDN'T JUST
TELL ME, BROTHER.
YOU JUST TOLD THE NATION.
WE'LL STIR IT UP A LITTLE BIT,
ADD SOME WATER,
AND WE'LL LET IT SOFTEN UP
WHILE WE MIX UP THE MEAT.
THAT LOOKS LIKE GROUND BEEF,
GROUND PORK.
YEP, BASICALLY
HALF-AND-HALF.
WE LIKE TO CALL IT 50-50.
50-50.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME RED WINE.
GONNA PUT SOME EGGS IN THERE.
ROCKY BALBOA MILKSHAKE.
AND SOME ONIONS
THAT WE SWEATED.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
JUMP RIGHT IN THERE
AND START
MIXING IT ALL UP.
IF IT WASN'T FOR ME
HOLDING THE TUB,
HE'D BE IN IT RIGHT NOW.
NEXT I'M GONNA ADD
THE BREAD CRUMB MIX.
NEW SHIRT, NEW SHIRT, EASY.
AND I WORE
THE LIGHT BLUE FOR YOU.
SO ARE THESE
MIXY-MIXIED ENOUGH?
YEAH. WE CAN START
MAKING 'EM.
OKAY. OH, WHAT'S THE "WE"?
START MAKING MEATBALLS HERE.
I THOUGHT I WOULD HELP YOU.
OH! ARE YOU REALLY--
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE ME DO--
HOW BIG OF A BALL
ARE WE MAKING?
ABOUT THAT BIG.
OKAY, SO NOW WE HAVE THESE.
WHAT THE--
YOU DID THAT ONE.
I DIDN'T DO THAT ONE.
YOU'RE GONNA LAY THE HOST
OUT ON THAT, HUH?
OKAY,
DO WE JUST "FLUNK"?
NO, I'M GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BUTTER DOWN
SO THEY GET NICE
AND BROWN AND CRISPY.
SO IT'S JUST
ROLL OUT THE BALLS?
YEP, WE'LL TURN 'EM
A LITTLE BIT,
GET A NICE LITTLE
CRUST ON 'EM.
I'M GONNA FINISH 'EM UP
IN THE OVEN.
DIG IT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA
PUT THESE IN--
JELLY, GRAVY, MY SHOE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE GRAVY FOR IT.
SO WE'LL START WITH BUTTER.
MAKING A ROUX?
YEAH. MIX IN A LITTLE FLOUR.
NEXT I'M GONNA ADD
HOMEMADE VEAL STOCK.
OKAY, YOU NEED ME HERE
ALL THE TIME.
YEAH, PLEASE. THAT'S GREAT.
WE GOT SOME PAN DRIPPINGS.
SO EVERY TIME
YOU MAKE THE MEATBALLS,
YOU SAVE THE DRIPPINGS?
EXACTLY. SOME CREAM.
GONNA ADD A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER, AND WE'RE DONE.
ARE THEY READY?
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S A MESS
OF MEATBALLS, BROTHER.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA SERVE WITH THESE?
SOME MASHED POTATOES,
PICKLED CUCUMBERS,
A LITTLE LINGONBERRY,
AND WE'RE GONNA TOP IT OFF
WITH THE GRAVY.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
THANKSGIVING DINNER.
VAR SA GOD.
VAR SA GOD?
YEAH, IT MEANS
"THERE YOU GO." HAVE AT IT.
MM. WOW, THAT'S NICE.
YOU GOTTA MIX THE LINGONBERRY
IN THERE...
OKAY.
FOR THE WHOLE EXPERIENCE.
MAN, THE MEATBALL HAS GOT
NICE TEXTURE ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT IT'S LIGHT
AND TENDER ON THE INSIDE.
JUST THINK ABOUT THAT
AS LIKE ROUND MEATLOAF.
GOT A LITTLE BIT MORE DEPTH
THAN JUST A REGULAR GRAVY.
THE LINGONBERRY'S
A LITTLE MORE TANGY.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW IF YOU
LIKE SCANDINAVIAN FOOD,
COME DOWN HERE AND TRY THOSE.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT.
THESE THINGS MAKE ME CRY,
THEY'RE SO GOOD.
SWEDISH MEATBALLS.
SWEET BERRY. A LITTLE SURPRISE
TO YOUR MASHED POTATOES.
BEAUTIFUL. A LITTLE MORE,
A LITTLE MORE.
JUST THE PERFECT BLEND.
THEY DO IT RIGHT?
YES, ABSOLUTELY. THIS IS LIKE
OUR FAVORITE RESTAURANT.
SALMON BENNY TO 15.
LET ME HAVE A LITTLE
MORE SMOKED SALMON.
COME ON, GUYS, LET'S GET
THIS STUFF OUTTA HERE.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
TEN-PLUS YEARS.
YOU LOVE IT HERE?
I CAN'T BE ANY MORE IMPRESSED,
MAN. CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
THAT IS REALLY--I MEAN, YOU GOT
SOMETHING FANTASTIC GOIN' ON.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
POSOLE.
WE'RE HEADING
TO MY HOMETOWN...
I LOVE
ALL THEIR FOOD HERE.
FOR MEXICAN COOKIN'...
SOPA de PICADILLO IS UP.
HEAVEN IN YOUR MOUTH.
SO GOOD.
DONE HER WAY.
YOU HAVE TO SHAKE
YOUR BOOTY.
THAT'S PART
OF COOKING IT?
YEAH, YEAH.
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY'S GOT
THEIR HOMETOWN FAVORITES.
HERE IN OUR HOMETOWN
OF SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA,
HUNTER AND I HAVE BEEN ROLLING
TO THIS PLACE FOR YEARS.
NOW THERE'S ALL KINDS OF
GREAT MEXICAN RESTAURANTS
IN THIS AREA,
BUT FOR SOME REASON,
BETWEEN THE STORY,
THE PEOPLE AND THE GREAT FOOD,
LA TEXANITA HAS BECOME
ONE OF OUR FAVORITES.
CHILE RELLENO'S UP!
WE'RE IN WINE COUNTRY,
BUT THIS...
THE HUARACHE.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN MEXICO
WHEN I'M HERE.
YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
CARNE ASADA TACOS.
WE TAKE 'EM DOWN.
AND THIS REALLY IS WHERE
I BRING MY FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
HOW IS IT, MOM?
FANTASTIC.
POSOLE.
EVERY TIME I BITE INTO IT,
IT REMINDS ME OF MEXICO.
'CAUSE OWNER ALMA MENDEZ...
CARNITAS.
GREW UP THERE.
ALMA, HOW LONG
HAVE I KNOWN YOU?
FIVE YEARS.
WE BOTH GET OUR HAIR DONE
BY THE SAME GUY.
THE HUARACHE CARNITAS
IS COMING.
WHERE DID YOU GET
ALL THE RECIPES FROM?
FROM MY MOM, MY SISTER.
WE HAVE OUR OWN WAY
TO MAKE OUR FOOD.
AND FOR ALMA,
IT'S STILL THE ONLY WAY.
(speaking Spanish)
YOU MAKE EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH?
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
THE SOPES, THE CARNE ASADA,
THE TORTILLAS, YOU NAME IT.
EVERYTHING.
THE HANDMADE TORTILLAS--
SO GOOD.
TORTILLAS UP.
IT MAKES A GREAT
DIFFERENCE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE REGULAR-SIZE
TORTILLAS FOR TACOS.
THIS STARTS
WITH ADDING THE MASA,
AND THIS IS DRIED CORN?
YEAH. WE USE WATER IN HERE.
THIS IS THE HARD PART--
GETTING THE MASA READY.
SO WE WANT IT TO BE
JUST A LITTLE BIT TACKY?
YEAH.
PUT IT IN A NICE, FIRM BALL
SO IT DOESN'T DRY OUT.
THAT'S ONE BIG TORTILLA.
YEP.
NOW WHERE DID THIS
COME FROM?
IT'S FROM MEXICO.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THIS ONE.
THIS IS LIKE THE TERMINATOR
OF TORTILLA MAKERS.
DID YOU KNOW THAT SOMEONE'S
PROBABLY GONNA STEAL THIS TODAY?
NO.
YEAH. NOW YOU PATTY YOURS
A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE YOU PUT IT DOWN?
YEAH, YOU HAVE
TO GO LIKE THIS...
THERE YOU GO.
AND YOU GOTTA MAKE THAT NOISE
WHEN YOU'RE DOING TORTILLAS.
OH, YOU DO?
OH, YEAH. AND PRESS,
AND THIS IS THE TORTILLA.
SO NOW
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CARNE ASADA TACOS.
THE FAMOUS CARNE ASADA
AT LA TEXANITA?
YES.
I'VE BEEN ASKING
FOR THIS RECIPE
SINCE I'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOR THE LAST FIVE YEARS.
BETTER NOT BE SUPER SIMPLE,
BECAUSE I'VE NEVER BEEN
ABLE TO FIGURE IT OUT.
IT'S REALLY SIMPLE.
AH!
WE HAVE SOME CHOPPED ONIONS.
COOK A LITTLE BIT--ONIONS HERE.
LIKE YOU'RE AIR DRUMMING.
WHEN WE HEAR THIS NOISE,
THAT MEANS THAT WE'RE COOKING.
PUT THE MEAT ON IT,
AND THEN WE ADD THE SALT.
WHEN YOU'RE CHOPPING,
YOU HAVE TO SHAKE YOUR BOOTY.
THAT'S PART
OF COOKING IT?
YEAH.
I WANT THIS TO BE
A BIG WINDOW HERE.
I'M DONE NOT BEING ABLE
TO SEE BACK HERE.
IT'S BEEN GOING
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
WHEN IT'S ALMOST READY,
WE ADD SOME LIME JUICE,
AND WE'RE DONE.
HERE'S THE TORTILLAS
THAT WE JUST MADE.
COOK 'EM UP UNTIL
THEY'RE NICE AND BROWN.
SO NOW WE'RE READY
TO MAKE OUR TACO.
WE HAVE TO PUT SOME ONIONS,
CILANTRO AND SOME SALSA.
AND YOU MAKE
THE SALSA, TOO.
WE MAKE THE SALSA.
WE ADD RADISHES, LIME
AND SOME JALAPEñOS,
AND THEY'RE READY TO GO.
LOOK AT THAT SETUP.
OH, SO SIMPLE,
BUT SO GOOD.
ONIONS ALMOST HAVE
THEIR OWN SWEETNESS TO 'EM,
AND THE NATURAL JUICES
AND THE FAT FROM THE MEAT
COOKED EVERYTHING,
BUT I'M TELLING YOU SOMETHING,
THERE'S JUST NOTHIN' THAT CAN
BEAT THE HANDMADE TORTILLA
AND COOKING IT
THE RIGHT WAY.
SHAKE YOUR BOOTY.
AND SHAKE YOUR BOOTY--
THE RIGHT WAY. GREAT JOB.
(man) TWO TACO READY!
THE CRUNCH OF THE ONION,
THE SOFTNESS OF THE TORTILLA--
JUST HEAVEN IN YOUR MOUTH.
READY--TWO TACOS UP!
THE MEAT'S WHAT MAKES IT,
IT'S JUST A DELICATE
TASTE TO IT.
IT'S THE MOST
AUTHENTIC TACO TRUCK
CARNE ASADA TACO
I COULD POSSIBLY GET.
'CAUSE IT ALL STARTED OUT
THAT WAY.
I HAD THE TACO TRUCK
FOR FIVE YEARS.
AND THEN YOU FOUND
THIS LOCATION.
THIS ONE FOR--
GONNA BE FIVE YEARS.
A LOT OF VARIETY FROM
DIFFERENT PARTS OF MEXICO.
TWO BURRITOS
AND ONE TORTA.
MOLCAJETE
MEAT AND VEGETABLES.
IN MEXICO, THE WOMEN
USE THAT TO MAKE SALSA.
(speaking Spanish)
HUARACHE.
IT'S BEANS IN BETWEEN TORTILLA
WITH CARNE ASADA, CREAM.
YUM. DELICIOUS.
MM. GREAT TEXTURE
OF THE CARNITAS.
THIN LAYER OF BEANS.
FANTASTIC DISH.
MM.
VERY GRACEFUL, HUH?
AVOCADOES WITH A BUNCH
OF THE JALAPEñOS.
IT'S GREAT.
I LOVE IT.
POSOLE.
A SOUP WITH HOMINY,
AND YOU GARNISH IT WITH ONION
AND CABBAGE. IT'S PERFECT.
MY PARENTS GO DOWN
TO MEXICO ALL THE TIME--
DAD, IN TERMS
OF THE POSOLE--
JUST LIKE IN COLIMA.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS--
THE POSOLE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
START OFF WITH?
BOILING WATER,
ONIONS.
SO IT'S GONNA SPEND
SO MUCH TIME IN THERE
THAT WE CAN JUST ADD
THE WHOLE ONION?
YEP.
AND THE WHOLE GARLIC?
YES. ADD THE SALT.
NOW WE HAVE TO ADD PORK MEAT.
PIG'S FEET?
PIG'S FEET.
THIS IS INTERESTING.
I DIDN'T KNOW
THERE WAS PIG'S FEET IN POSOLE.
YOU'RE NUMBER ONE.
REMEMBER WHEN WE WENT
TO MAMA E's
IN OKLAHOMA CITY, OKLAHOMA?
THE HOOF IS THE BEST.
GIVE ME A HIGH HOOF.
ALL RIGHT.
THOSE WERE SOME
DYNAMITE PIG'S FEET.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK?
FOR AN HOUR.
SO THE ONION SEPARATED APART,
THE PORK'S STILL BOILING.
NOW WE HAVE TO ADD
THE POSOLE.
OKAY, SO THIS IS CORN
THAT'S BEEN SOAKED.
YES.
WE ADD SOME CHICKEN BASE,
THE GUAJILLO SAUCE.
AND HERE'S THE GUAJILLO.
THIS IS THE GUAJILLO CHILE.
WE TOOK THE STEMS OFF,
TOOK THE SEEDS OUT,
LET 'EM SIT THERE AND STEEP,
BLENDED 'EM WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
THEN RAN IT
THROUGH THE STRAINER.
MAKES THIS REALLY NICE
ALMOST LIKE ENCHILADA SAUCE.
THIS IS KIND OF REALLY
THE FLAVOR BASE OF THIS.
YEAH, THIS IS GONNA BE
SITTING HERE FOR 20 MINUTES,
THEN READY TO SERVE.
THIS IS--
THE BACKBONE,
AND THERE'S SOME FEET.
JUST NOT EVERY DAY
THAT YOU GET OFFERED THAT.
LOOK AT THAT COLOR
FROM THE HOMINY.
I'M SORRY. I STARTED
TO DROOL A LITTLE BIT.
WE HAVE THIS ON THE SIDE--
CABBAGE, SALSA,
RADISHES, ONION AND LIME.
AND THEN YOU CAN KINDA
MAKE IT THE WAY YOU WANT?
YEAH, AND WE HAVE
SOME TOSTADAS.
WHEN I AM HOME,
OFF THE ROAD FROM TRIPLE "D,"
DEFINITELY ONE OF MY STOPS
IS COMING BY LA TEXANITA
TO GET THIS.
MMM.
THIS IS ABOUT AS REAL-DEAL
AS YOU CAN GET.
THE HOMINY
HAS NICE TEXTURE.
I LOVE GETTIN' THE CABBAGE
AND THE ONIONS IN THERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC. THE BROTH
IS REALLY NICE AND LIGHT.
ADDING THINGS
LIKE THE PIG'S FEET--
JUST GET
REAL FLAVORS IN THERE.
I HAVE GOT TO ADMIT
I DIG THE HOOF.
REALLY RICH FLAVOR--IT TASTES
LIKE FRESH CORN ON THE COB
WHEN YOU BITE
INTO THE HOMINY.
FIRST THING THAT I NOTICE
IS THE PORK--
REALLY SOFT AND JUICY.
POSOLE UP.
EVERY SINGLE SPICE HAS A LITTLE
PIECE OF MEXICO IN IT.
(speaking Spanish)
THIS IS WHY WE COME HERE--
REAL AS IT GETS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SOPA de PICADILLO IS UP.
EVERYTHING IS AUTHENTIC,
NICE AND FRESH.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S BEEN
REALLY FUN FOR ME?
IS I NEVER KNEW WHAT WENT ON
BEHIND THE SCENES.
I JUST KNEW THE FOOD
THAT CAME OUT OF
THE LITTLE WINDOW WAS GREAT.
I'M SO PROUD OF YOU.
THANKS.
NEXT STOP...
THIS IS WONDERFUL FOOD.
BEEF COUNTRY...
LOOK AT THAT.
AS TEXAS...
I LOVE THE MASHWI SHISH.
MEETS THE MIDDLE EAST.
TABBOULEH IS DONE.
THE HUMMUS IS THE BEST.
MMM. THAT'S FALAFEL-ISTIC.
NOW I'M A DRIVE-IN MAGNET.
IF IT'S A DRIVE-IN MAKING KILLER
FOOD, I'LL PROBABLY FIND IT,
AND HERE I AM
IN NORTH ARLINGTON, TEXAS,
AT WHAT USED TO BE
A FAST FOOD DRIVE-IN
TURNED INTO THIS PLACE--
PRINCE LEBANESE GRILL.
ONE SHISH TAOUK
IS READY, SIR.
IT IS JUST INCREDIBLE.
IT'S GREAT.
THIS IS WONDERFUL FOOD.
THE HUMMUS IS THE BEST.
BEEF AND CHICKEN
SHAWARMA.
WHEN YOU'VE GOT THE NEED,
THE NEED FOR LEBANESE...
THIS IS WHERE YOU GO.
TABBOULEH IS DONE.
IT'S THE KIND OF FOOD
FRANCIS KOBTY
GREW UP WITH
IN THE MIDDLE EAST.
TWO FALAFELS.
WE TRY TO MAKE IT
AS ORIGINAL AS POSSIBLE.
HE CAME TO THE STATES
30 YEARS AGO...
YOUR PRINCE IS READY.
THANK YOU, SIR.
AND BROUGHT HIS NICKNAME
WITH HIM.
SO YOU'RE THE PRINCE?
PRINCE OF THE LEBANESE
FOOD, I GUESS.
BRING IT.
AND NOW HE'S GOT
A WHOLE LOT OF TEXANS...
CHICKEN'S SO GOOD.
EATING HIS WAY.
I COME HERE
ALL THE TIME.
SERIOUSLY--
I LOVE THIS PLACE, YEAH.
PROBABLY TWICE A WEEK.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
I NEED THE MASHWI SHISH.
I LOVE THE MASHWI SHISH.
IT'S THE BEEF.
NOT JUST ANY BEEF.
I USE THE TOP-OF-THE-LINE
STUFF ON IT.
BEEF TENDERLOIN.
YOU'RE IN TEXAS.
YEAH.
HOW MANY PIECES
COME IN AN ORDER?
THREE PIECES.
EVERYBODY OUT OF THE POOL.
EXACTLY.
MONTREAL STEAK SEASONING.
YES, SIR.
A LITTLE MUSTARD SEED,
CORIANDER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH WHAT WE CALL AN ALLSPICE.
IS ALLSPICE PRETTY PREDOMINANT
IN LEBANESE FOOD?
THEY USE IT ON EVERYTHING
THAT THEY HAVE.
OKAY, SO WE GOT THAT
ALL SEASONED UP.
THIS IS OLIVE OIL.
FROM LEBANON.
THAT'S THE ONE
I REALLY LIKE.
NOW WILL YOU LET
THIS MARINATE?
FOR ALMOST ABOUT 24 HOURS.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
YOU JUST MIX IT UP
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
THIS WAS IMPORTED
FROM SCHENECTADY.
NICE!
WE'RE GONNA START
THE RICE PILAF.
WE GET SOME VERMICELLI
AND WE FRY IT.
THIS IS CORN OIL.
THIS IS HOW I START OFF
ALL MY DISHES--
FRYING MY UNCOOKED PASTA.
JUST WAIT UNTIL IT BECOMES
A LITTLE BIT MORE BROWN.
PUT THE RICE IN THERE,
AND THE RICE HAS ALREADY BEEN
SOAKED AND WASHED.
MM-HMM.
WHAT ARE WE DOING HERE?
THIS IS OUR CHICKEN BROTH.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
CHICKEN STOCK?
YES, AND THIS IS OUR MIXTURE
OF ABOUT 14 DIFFERENT SPICES.
PUT SOME WATER IN HERE.
OKAY.
SO DRIED HERBS,
CHICKEN STOCK,
FRIED VERMICELLI
AND SOME BASMATI RICE,
AND YOU, TOO,
CAN START YOUR RICE PILAF
AT YOUR LEBANESE DRIVE-IN
THAT YOU FIND IN TEXAS
BETWEEN A BUNCH OF MEXICAN
RESTAURANTS CLOSE TO A HOSPITAL.
COVER IT AND LET IT
SIT FOR A LITTLE BIT.
ON HEAT
OR OFF OF HEAT?
NO, ON HEAT.
NICE HOT GRILL.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT VINEGAR
COMIN' UP RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
NEXT THING THAT HITS YOU
RIGHT THERE IS THE ALLSPICE.
OH, YES.
AND WHAT TYPICALLY
GETS SERVED WITH THIS?
GRILLED ONION,
GRILLED TOMATOES
AND THE GREEN PEPPER.
WE GONNA PUT ANY OIL
OR ANYTHING ON THE--
NO, WE DON'T DO
ANYTHING ELSE.
GOOD. I WAS JUST
MAKING SURE.
CUT IT INTO A BUTTERFLY.
OH, OH. LOOK AT THAT.
SO IS OUR RICE READY?
OUR RICE IS EXCELLENT.
WHOA.
YOU'RE TAKING THIS "THEY DO IT
BIGGER IN TEXAS" THING
SERIOUSLY, AREN'T YOU?
YES.
'CAUSE I'M A STARCH JUNKIE,
YOU KNOW I GOTTA
GO AFTER THIS PILAF FIRST.
OH, OH. GREAT TEXTURE.
VERY CREAMY. IT'S ALMOST
LIKE YOU PUT BUTTER IN IT.
MMM. ALL RIGHT.
SO HERE WE ARE
WITH SOME FILET.
THAT'S GREAT.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THAT IS--I MEAN,
THAT'S KILLER.
THANK YOU.
MMM. DO YOU AIRMAIL?
LOAD A TRUNK UP?
I'LL DRIVE IT
UP THERE FOR YOU.
LIGHTLY SEASONED--
NOT OVER-SEASONED.
SERVED WITH DELICIOUS PILAF
HANDMADE BY THE GUY
IN THE DRESS SHIRT.
YOU GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
THE MOST TENDER BEEF
I'VE HAD.
THE RICE
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
IT'S JUST, LIKE, PERFECT.
THE MAIN THING--
IS ALL FRESH.
MY MOM USED TO GO TO THE STORE--
SHE NEVER BUYS CANNED FOOD.
WE NEVER HAD CANNED FOODS
IN THE HOUSE.
AND THE PRINCE IS STILL
DOING IT ALL MOM'S WAY.
YEAH, I NEED
SOME TOMATOES.
FROM TABBOULEH
WITH PARSLEY, TOMATO,
BULGAR WHEAT,
SPICES AND MINT...
THE TABBOULEH.
THE TABBOULEH'S WONDERFUL.
TO THE EGGPLANT DIP
CALLED BABA GHANOUSH...
OH, MAN, I LOVE THAT STUFF.
TO THIS CLASSIC...
FALAFEL PLATE
ON TABLE FOUR.
I LOVE THE FALAFEL.
WE'RE GETTING INTO
MAKING SOME FALAFELS.
YOU TAKE THE GARBANZO BEANS
AND YOU SOAK THEM...
OVERNIGHT.
OVERNIGHT
TO RECONSTITUTE THEM.
YES.
WE MIX SOME OF THAT
PARSLEY AND ONION,
GARLIC, OUR HOT PEPPERS,
A LITTLE BIT MORE OF AN ONION.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THAT
GOLD RING YOU HAD ON?
OH, IT'S SOMEWHERE
IN THERE, I GUESS.
WE'VE MOVED FROM CHICKPEA
SPAGHETTI INTO WHEAT GRASS.
BLACK PEPPER IN HERE.
ANOTHER ONE OF THOSE
FINE MEASURING TECHNIQUES.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
MMM.
CUMIN POWDER,
A LITTLE BIT OF BAKING SODA
TO MAKE IT FLUFFY
WHEN I FRY IT.
NOW DO WE LET THIS SET?
WE LET IT SET
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO IS--
THAT'S COOL.
IT USED TO BE A SPOON,
WAY BACK.
HE TOOK THE SPOON--
JUST HAMMER. PULL IT BACK.
JUST SPREAD IT AROUND.
PULL IT BACK.
SO NOT A LOT OF PRESSURE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S AWESOME. ALL RIGHT,
NOW WE FRY THESE BAD BOYS?
THAT'S 1040, RIGHT?
YEAH, 1040. THIS IS ACTUALLY
WHAT YOU CALL CORN OIL.
I LIKE THE WOK.
I SAY, "WOK," HE WALKS AWAY.
GONNA FEED THE TOWN,
OR WHAT?
NORMALLY, IT COMES
12 IN AN ORDER.
FALAFEL NUGGETS
OF FRIENDSHIP RIGHT THERE.
THOSE ARE YOUR BREADS.
THIS IS THE HUMMUS.
PICKLES OR SKINNED LIZARD?
SKINNED LIZARD,
WITH THE--A LITTLE BIT
OF A TAHINI SAUCE.
MIXED A LITTLE BIT
OF A GARLIC LEMON JUICE.
A DROP OF OLIVE OIL ON THERE,
AND THEN WE GET THE FALAFEL.
THE TAHINI.
YES, YOU COULD SMASH
THE FALAFELS WITH THE BREAD.
THAT'S FUNNY.
THIS IS MINE.
OKAY.
WHERE'S YOURS?
WANNA SHOW ME HOW?
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
ONE OF THOSE. THERE YOU GO.
WOW.
I THINK THE FALAFEL,
AS IT IS, IS GREAT,
BUT YOU GOTTA PUT THE PICKLE
AND TOMATO IN THERE.
THAT GIVES IT
MORE FLAVOR.
THAT'S FALAFEL-ISTIC.
FROM THE PRINCE
OF NORTH ARLINGTON.
PRINCE OF NORTH ARLINGTON,
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S REALLY CRISPY
ON THE OUTSIDE,
AND YOU CAN STILL TASTE WHAT
ALL OF THE DIFFERENT SPICES ARE
ON THE INSIDE.
IT'S GREAT.
IT TASTES GREAT.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD
HERE IS WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU.
IT IS SIMPLE FOOD,
BUT THEY TAKE THEIR TIME.
AND SPEAKING OF TIME...
I GOT A THYME PIE.
MIDDLE EASTERN BREAKFAST PIZZA
HE'S SERVING ALL DAY...
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
I'VE EVER EATEN BEFORE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
TWO FALAFELS,
TWO TABBOULEH, READY TO GO.
AT PRINCE LEBANESE GRILL
IN NORTH ARLINGTON, TEXAS...
HOW WE DOIN'?
WE'RE GOIN' WELL.
FRANCIS KOBTY,
A.K.A. "PRINCE"--
ONE MORE SHISH TAOUK.
IS WINNING OVER
THE LOCALS.
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
THAT I ACTUALLY CRAVE.
I'VE BEEN HOOKED
ON THE CHICKEN SHAWARMA.
SHISH TAOUK.
SOUNDS LIKE
A "STAR WARS" DISH.
GIVE ME
TWO OF THE WOOKIEES!
IT'S JUST WONDERFUL.
IT'S A GREAT OPPORTUNITY TO TRY
A LOT OF DIFFERENT THINGS.
LIKE THIS ONE.
THYME PIE.
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
I'VE EVER EATEN BEFORE.
MMM.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING,
PRINCE?
WE'RE MAKING THE THYME PIE.
LET ME GET STRAIGHT
WHAT'S IN HERE.
ZA'ATAR PLANT, SESAME SEEDS,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
TASTES LIKE A LITTLE BIT
OF OREGANO.
IT'S SIMILAR TO OREGANO.
IT'S NOT OREGANO.
WE CALL IT ZA'ATAR.
WHY DO YOU CALL IT
THYME PIE?
IT'S KIND OF HARD
FOR PEOPLE TO SAY "ZA'ATAR,"
SO WE AMERICANIZE IT
A LITTLE BIT.
SO YOU JUST GO TO A MIDDLE
EASTERN STORE AND BUY THIS?
YEAH, I'LL CALL
MY MOM AND--
OH, YEAH, WELL, EVERYBODY'S
GONNA GET YOUR MOM ON THE PHONE.
OKAY.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF
THE TOMATOES, SOME DICED ONIONS,
PUT SOME OLIVE OIL
IN THERE.
GOT A MIDDLE EASTERN
PESTO-LOOKING MIXTURE THERE.
JUST MIX IT UP
REAL GOOD.
PIZZA BREADS.
DID YOU JUST CHUCK IT?
YEAH, CHUCK IT IN THERE.
OKAY, WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS PUT SOME HERE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
EAT IT AS BREAKFAST.
MY KIDS EAT ENGLISH MUFFIN
WITH PEANUT BUTTER,
AND YOURS BUST DOWN WITH SOME
OF THE ZA'ATAR AND SOME ONIONS.
YOU'RE DOING A LOT OF STUDYING,
THEY USED TO TELL US,
"YOU HAVE TO EAT
THE ZA'ATAR IN THE MORNING.
IT'S GOOD FOR YOUR BRAIN."
WELL, THAT EXPLAINS IT.
THE ZA'ATAR IS A STARTER.
AND THE ZA'ATAR
IS THE AWESOME STUFF HERE.
THAT DIDN'T RHYME AT ALL.
IT'S READY TO GO.
FOR BREAKFAST?
MMM.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
GOOD ONE?
GREAT ONE.
I LIKE SOUR, TANGY,
CRUNCHY, SALTY--
THIS IS ALL OF THAT.
IT'S GOT A COMBINATION
OF IT.
THIS HAS GOT IT ALL.
THAT'S CRAZY.
IT'S GOT A REAL--
TEXTURE.
REAL DEEP FLAVOR TO IT.
THAT'S GREAT. I'D LIKE
A LITTLE CHEESE ON THAT.
YOU COULD PUT
GRILLED CHICKEN ON THAT.
YOU COULD PUT LETTUCE.
I MEAN, THAT'S--
I WOULD TAKE THAT INTO
LEBANESE TOSTADA. MMM.
I'VE ALREADY HAD ONE.
I'M HAVING ANOTHER.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD THE THYME
PIZZA THAT HAS NO THYME?
NO.
NO? REALLY?
I WILL TRY THAT, THOUGH.
OH, YOU DO.
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE TIME.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN GREAT.
THE SHISH TAOUK IS ON.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL?
DEFINITELY.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
I LOVE IT.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
THE PEOPLE ARE GREAT.
HELLO, HOW ARE YOU?
I JUST LOVE RESTAURANTS,
AND I JUST WANNA BE COOKING
AND BE INVOLVED WITH PEOPLE.
HOW YOU GUYS DOIN'?
GREAT JOB. GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THIS GUY--THE PRINCE
OF NORTH ARLINGTON.
THERE YOU GO.
AH!
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY--
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪