HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOO-HOO.
BARBECUED, BAKED AND BRINED.
GOSH, THIS IS GONNA BE MELT
IN YOUR MOUTH OR MELT IN MOUTH.
IN CLEVELAND...
BISCUIT UP.
ALL OF HER FOOD'LL TASTE
AS GOOD AS IT LOOKS.
WHERE THIS...
HOW LONG WILL
WE LET THIS BRINE?
SEVEN DAYS.
IS HOW YOU BUILD
A RUEBEN SANDWICH.
MMM! LOOK AT
THE GOOSEBUMPS ON MY ARM.
AND LOOK
WHO'S STOPPING BY.
HOW ARE YOU?
IRON CHEF MICHAEL SYMON.
YOU GUYS KNOW EACH OTHER?
NO, I WALK INTO A KITCHEN,
I KISS THE FIRST WOMAN I SEE.
IN CHICAGO...
HERE WE GO.
THE MEAT IS SO GOOD, YOU COULD
JUST TELL IT'S HOMEMADE.
BARBECUE....
THE BEST I EVER HAD
IN MY LIFE.
THE MEMPHIS WAY.
MMM. OH, DUDE. DIG IT.
AND THEY'VE GOT THE CREDS
TO BACK IT UP.
AND THAT TOOK THIRD PLACE
IN MEMPHIS IN MAY.
YES, SIR.
I CAN'T WAIT.
AND IN IDAHO...
LET'S KICK
THESE PIZZAS OFF FIRST.
YES, SIR.
WHERE IT'S ALL
IN A NAME.
PIZZA, SALAD AND CHICKEN--
PIZZALCHIK.
THE SALADS DON'T
LOOK LIKE WHAT YOU EXPECT.
AND THIS KID CAN TOSS
A SERIOUS SKIN.
I LIKE THE WAY
IT'S LOOKING.
GENTLE HAND THAT
DOESN'T TEAR THROUGH IT.
PIZZA KILLERS RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D,"
PEOPLE ARE ALWAYS ASKING ME,
HEY, GUY, IF IT'S NOT A DINER
AND IT'S NOT A DRIVE-IN,
THEN IS IT A DIVE?
AND I LIKE TO SAY, YOU KNOW,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
I MEAN, WHAT IT'S REALLY ABOUT
IS REAL PEOPLE MAKING REAL FOOD,
KINDA LIKE THIS JOINT
HERE IN CLEVELAND,
WHERE IT'S ALL ABOUT
FARM TO TABLE AT LUCKY'S CAFé.
OKAY, GRANOLA.
A LOT OF FRESH INGREDIENTS,
A LOT OF LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
SPINACH AND MUSHROOM
OMELET.
AND THEY GROW VEGGIES OUT
IN THE BACKYARD.
YOUR OWN
ROMAINE LETTUCE?
YEP.
(man) ALWAYS GOOD.
MONEY?
MONEY.
HIGHEST QUALITY
FOOD AROUND.
BEING PREPARED
WITH A LOT OF LOVE.
BY OWNER HEATHER HAVILAND...
WAFFLE.
WHO STARTED HERE
SIX YEARS AGO
WHEN THE PLACE
WAS A COFFEE SHOP,
AND SHE RENTED PART OF IT
FOR A BAKING BUSINESS.
AND I STARTED BAKING THINGS
OUT OF THE STORAGE CLOSET.
THREE YEARS LATER,
SHE BOUGHT INTO THE PLACE,
FILLED OUT THE KITCHEN...
MAC AND CHEESE.
AND FILLED UP THE MENU.
MAC AND CHEESE
WITH HOUSE-MADE APPLESAUCE.
ALWAYS SOMETHING NEW.
AND ALMOST EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH.
BISCUIT UP.
EVERYTHING THAT
COMES OUT OF THAT KITCHEN...
FROM BURRITOS TO BISCUITS,
AND, YEAH, JUST A BASIC REUBEN
HOMEMADE CORNED BEEF,
HOMEMADE SAUERKRAUT.
THOUSAND ISLAND
THEY MAKE IN-HOUSE.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE PICKLES
AND KETCHUP.
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE BRINE
ACTUALLY FOR THE BRISKET
FOR THE REUBEN.
2 GALLONS OF WATER.
KOSHER SALT.
KOSHER SALT, THEN WE'VE GOT
SUGAR, GARLIC CLOVES,
CURING SALT...
THERE YOU GO. YOU GOTTA
HAVE A LITTLE PINK NITRATE.
PEPPERCORN, FRESH GINGER,
BAY LEAVES, CINNAMON STICKS,
GROUND MACE.
WHICH IS
THE OUTSIDE COATING...
I LOVE THAT, YES.
OF THE NUTMEG.
AND IT GROWS LIKE HANDS,
LIKE THIS.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
WHOLE CLOVES,
ALLSPICE, RED PEPPER FLAKES,
CORIANDER ACTUALLY
FROM OUR GARDEN...
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
MUSTARD SEED, AND THEN
WE BRING IT TO A BOIL,
AND THEN LET IT
COOL COMPLETELY.
SO WE'VE GOT THIS BIG
MONSTER PIECE OF BRISKET.
YEP, AND THEN WE'RE GONNA POUR
OUR BEAUTIFUL BRINE ONTO THERE.
MMM.
I KNOW WE'RE DOING GOOD.
I KNOW THAT'S GONNA BE SOME
RIGHTEOUS CORNED BEEF.
HOW LONG WILL
WE LET THIS BRINE?
SEVEN DAYS, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT UP
AND MOVE IT OUT OF HERE
AND STRAIN IT.
TO CATCH
THE HERBS AND SPICES.
ALL THAT MAGIC.
PUT THAT INTO THE POT.
GOSH, THIS IS GONNA BE
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH
OR MELT IN MY MOUTH.
AND FRESH THYME.
WHICH WAS
OUT IN THE GARDEN.
YES.
WHEN YOU JUST PICK IT,
THE BOUQUET IS ENORMOUS.
PERFUME.
CARROTS, ONION, CELERY.
AND THEN FRESH WATER.
SO YOU'LL BRING
IT TO A BOIL?
AND THEN COVER IT
AND SIMMER IT FOR THREE HOURS.
DIG IT, AND THEN
I'LL EAT ALL OF IT.
YOU'LL EAT
THE WHOLE THING.
HERE'S OUR CORNED BEEF
COOLED AND READY TO SLICE
AND WHAT'S GONNA
COME ON THIS SANDWICH?
RYE BREAD. I USE THAT
JUST AS A MEDIUM.
BUFFER.
YES.
BUT WE MAKE OUR OWN RYE BREAD,
SO I REALLY WOULD PREFER...
OF COURSE WE DO.
THAT YOU NOT
USE IT AS A BUFFER.
WELL, OF COURSE WE MAKE
OUR OWN RYE BREAD.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER. SWISS.
SO YOU MAKE THE BREAD,
YOU MAKE THE CORNED BEEF.
RIGHT.
YOU MAKE THE SAUERKRAUT.
YEP, IN-HOUSE.
CORNED BEEF.
HMM, SHE'S USING THE KRAUT
TO HEAT UP THE CORNED BEEF,
SO IT'S NOT GETTING A TEXTURE
OF BEING COOKED ON THE FLAT TOP.
YES.
AND THEN COVER IT AND DISH UP
SOME THOUSAND ISLAND.
FOR THE THOUSAND ISLAND
DRESSING,
WE GROW OUR CUCUMBERS,
MAKE THOSE INTO PICKLES.
WE MAKE OUR OWN KETCHUP.
WE PUT LOCAL HONEY IN THERE.
ADD THE MAYONNAISE. YOU MAKE
A THOUSAND ISLAND DRESSING.
AND THEN--
LOOK AT THAT.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF I'M WORTHY TO EAT THIS.
THEY SHOULD HAVE A SHOT
OF THAT IN THE LOUVRE.
I DON'T
HAVE ANYTHING TO SAY.
LOOK AT THE GOOSEBUMPS
ON MY ARM.
THAT BREAD, THAT KRAUT,
WITH THAT CORNED--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S BETTER
ON ALL OF THIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HIT
THE THOUSAND ISLAND.
MMM.
I DON'T KNOW THAT YOU SHOULD
ACCEPT MONEY FOR THESE.
BRING US YOUR FIRSTBORN.
RICH, BUTTERY,
IT'S YUMMY.
ALL THE STUFF COMES
RIGHT FROM THE GARDEN OUTSIDE.
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
ISN'T THAT AMAZING?
I-I-I LOVE THAT.
NO, WHAT'S AMAZING
IS YOU.
ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
I HAVEN'T HAD ONE ITEM HERE
THAT I HAVEN'T LIKED.
HOW WAS BRUNCH TODAY?
IT WAS GREAT.
ALL OF HER FOOD
IS BEAUTIFUL,
AND IT TASTES
AS GOOD AS IT LOOKS.
HOLY GRANOL-Y,
HOW WAS THAT?
I LOVE IT.
WHEN IT'S MADE
IN-HOUSE EVERY DAY,
YOU CAN REALLY TELL
THE DIFFERENCE.
TA-DA.
I FEEL LIKE I'M TAKING A BIT
OF THE MONA LISA RIGHT NOW. MMM.
IF YOUR KID IS HOOKED
ON SUGAR CEREAL, BRING HIM
TO THE RECOVERY CENTER
AND GIVE HIM SOME OF THIS.
(laughing)
TONS OF FLAVOR.
YOU GET ALL THE LOCAL FRUITS
WITH GRANOLA
THAT SHE DOES HERSELF.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
SHE COMES UP WITH
REALLY CREATIVE IDEAS.
STEEL-CUT OATMEAL.
(woman) WITH BAKED APPLE.
IT TASTES LIKE AN APPLE PIE.
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
WAFFLES, PEACH COMPOTE,
CARAMEL ON TOP.
I REALLY LOVE
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
FOUR MINUTES TILL BISCUIT.
HOMEMADE BISCUITS,
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE GRAVY--
IT'S FANTASTIC.
WHAT KIND OF SAUSAGE
ARE WE MAKING?
BREAKFAST SAUSAGE
THAT THEN WE'RE GONNA TURN
INTO SAUSAGE GRAVY.
SO THIS IS PORK BUTT
WITH A NICE AMOUNT OF FAT.
IS THIS LOCAL PORK?
YES, OF COURSE,
AND OUR BUTCHER--
YOU KNEW
THIS PIG PROBABLY.
YEAH.
WE FOUND ONE OF TWO CERTIFIED
ORGANIC BUTCHERS IN OHIO.
OKAY, SO THIS IS ALL GONNA
GO IN THE GRINDER.
YES.
THAT'S GORGEOUS.
LOOK AT THIS.
BEAUTIFUL.
LET ME LICK THE BOWL,
LET ME LICK THE BOWL.
NO!
ICE WATER.
AND THE ICE WATER
BECAUSE...
IT BINDS EVERYTHING AND ALSO
HELPS DISSOLVE THE SPICES.
GROUND CLOVES, GROUND GINGER,
GROUND CAYENNE PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER, SAVORY,
DRIED THYME, MARJORAM.
THIS IS FRESH SAGE.
AND SAGE AND PORK
ARE LIKE MICKEY AND MOUSE.
YES, SOME KOSHER SALT.
OKAY, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THAT?
WELL, WHAT
I WANT YOU TO DO
IS JUST RUN YOUR FINGERS
THROUGH MY HAIR.
OKAY, VEGETABLE OIL,
RAW PORK BUTT.
SO YOU BREAK THIS
ALL DOWN.
I DO COOK IT
ALL THE WAY.
YOU BEST BE LEARNING HOW
TO MAKE SOME GRAVY, BUDDY.
OHH! HEY, BUDDY!
'CAUSE DADDY'S HUNGRY.
HOW ARE YOU, BROTHER?
KNOW WHO THIS IS?
IRON CHEF MICHAEL SYMON.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HE'S A CLEVELAND GUY.
I GUESS YOU GUYS
KNOW EACH OTHER.
YEAH. NO, I JUST
WALK INTO A KITCHEN,
I KISS
THE FIRST WOMAN I SEE.
UH, IT WORKS.
MICHAEL, YOU'RE HERE IN TOWN.
YOU HAVE LOLITA?
LOLITA,
LOLA AND BAR SYMON.
SO HAVE YOU HAD THE BISCUITS
AND GRAVY HERE BEFORE?
OH, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, LET ME
GET A RUNDOWN HERE.
SO NOW WE'RE
GONNA STRAIN THE FAT.
RIGHT.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA
USE ALL THE FAT.
WE'RE GONNA USE
EVERY LAST DROP.
TRUST ME--NOTHING
GOES TO WASTE IN THIS JOINT.
OKAY, WE EVAPORATE A LITTLE
OF THE MOISTURE OUT OF THERE
DOWN TO ALMOST PURE FAT.
YEP.
AND GROUND NUTMEG, CAYENNE,
SOME FRESH SAGE.
OKAY, ALL-PURPOSE?
FLOUR, HEAVY CREAM.
WHOA, WHOA, LOOK
AT THE COLOR OF THIS.
MM-HMM, GRASS-FED.
SALT.
A LITTLE WHOLE MILK. NOW
WE'RE ADDING SWEATED ONIONS.
SWEATED ONIONS.
YOU WANT ME TO WHISK
WHILE YOU POUR?
OH, YOU ARE GOOD.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
I'M THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
DUDE.
THEN THE SAUSAGE,
ONE OF THE BEST GRAVIES
IN TOWN YOU'D SAY.
OHH.
OH, MAYBE THE BEST GRAVY
IN THE COUNTRY.
YOU ARE SO KIND.
THIS IS THE TOASTED
CHEDDAR BISCUITS.
WHY ARE THERE TWO PLATES?
JUST YOU AND ME, HEATHER?
PUT SCALLIONS
RIGHT ON TOP.
WOW.
OH, THIS IS NUTS.
SAGE, MEAT,
THE SCALLION, THE CHEDDAR.
I LIKE THAT THERE'S
TEXTURE TO THE BISCUIT,
BECAUSE THEN IT BECOMES
REFORTIFIED INSIDE OF THE GRAVY,
HITTING THOSE ONIONS
AT THE LAST MOMENT.
YEAH, A LITTLE SHARP AT THE END,
CUTS THROUGH THE RICHNESS.
AND YOU CAN TASTE THE CHEDDAR
IN THE BISCUITS. WHAT'S THAT?
WHAT? OH, HE THINKS
THIS IS MY FIRST RODEO? NO.
HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE GRAVY
AND BISCUITS?
JUST A BIG PLATE
OF SAVORY GOODNESS.
THE CHEDDAR
AND THE SCALLIONS MAKE IT.
THE SAUSAGE
IS VERY GOOD, TOO.
EVERYTHING ON THE PLATE
IS GREAT AND LOCALLY GROWN
AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE,
WHICH I THINK IS REALLY COOL.
SHE'S DOING IT WITH SUCH PASSION
AND SUCH LOVE.
THIS HAS BEEN AWESOME.
WHAT A VISIT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THANKS FOR
COMING BY, BROTHER.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
UP NEXT...
(man) ORDER UP.
WE'RE HEADING TO CHICAGO...
I LOVE THE DRY RUB.
CAN YOU FINISH IT?
I'M ABOUT TO.
FOR A BARBECUE...
GREAT SMOKE RING.
DONE MEMPHIS STYLE.
BRISKET ON A STICK.
I'M HERE IN ONE OF THE MAIN
ARTERIES IN CHICAGO,
18th STREET,
AT A BUILDING THAT, GET THIS,
WAS ONCE HOME TO
A CZECHOSLOVAKIAN SOCIAL CLUB.
SO WHAT DOES ONE DO WHEN
THEY OWN 24,000 SQUARE FEET
AND FOUR STORIES
OF COMMERCIAL REAL ESTATE?
HUH, LET ME THINK.
OH, YEAH, I GOT IT.
HOW ABOUT TURNING IT
INTO AN AWARD-WINNING
BARBECUE RESTAURANT?
YEAH, THAT'S THE TICKET. HERE
YOU ARE--HONKY TONK BARBECUE.
HERE WE GO.
NICE.
IT WAS THE BEST BARBECUE
I EVER HAD.
(man)
THE BRISKET SANDWICH.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT IT
IS IT FALLS APART. MMM.
YOU'RE GONNA PLEDGE
YOUR ALLEGIANCE?
TO HONKY TONK.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
THE MEAT IS SO GOOD YOU COULD
JUST TELL IT'S HOMEMADE.
ORDER UP.
THE WAY WILLIE WAGNER'S
BEEN MAKING IT
FOR 25 YEARS.
I'M SELF-TAUGHT,
BUT I REALLY LEARNED HOW
TO DO THE SERIOUS BARBECUE
ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO.
WHEN HE STARTED
WITH A TRAVELING RIG.
PEOPLE WOULD LOVE
TO SEE IT COMING 'CAUSE THEY
COULD SMELL IT A MILE AWAY.
AND NOW HE'S BROUGHT IT INTO
THIS RESTAURANT ATMOSPHERE.
THERE WE GO.
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
LOOK AT THAT NICE
BURNED EDGE ON THERE.
(Guy) WHAT KIND OF BARBECUE
WOULD YOU SAY YOU MAKE?
THIS IS A MEMPHIS DRY RUB
SERVED WITHOUT SAUCE.
AND THE FIRST INGREDIENT IS
A BARBECUE SEASONING BLEND.
IT'S GOT SOME ONIONS,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
SALT, SUGAR,
PAPRIKA, GARLIC.
CHILI POWDER, DARK.
AND THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT
EACH TIME? YOU EYEBALL IT?
OH, YEAH. SPANISH PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
RUBBED SAGE.
A LITTLE ONION POWDER,
CORIANDER, DRIED GINGER,
CUMIN AND WE GOT
THREE FLAVORS OF PEPPER--
CAYENNE, BLACK
AND WHITE PEPPER.
OKAY, THAT'S A RUB.
FOR JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING HERE...
(woman) BRISKET?
CHICKEN, RIB TIPS...
THAT'S GOOD EATIN'.
AND WILLIE'S AWARD-WINNING
PULLED PORK.
BEEN TO MEMPHIS IN MAY.
AND YOU TOOK
3rd PLACE IN 2008?
YES, SIR.
I GOTTA EXPLAIN
SOMETHING TO YOU FOLKS--
THAT IS INCREDIBLE.
THE COMPETITION LEVEL THAT
MEMPHIS IN MAY IS... (whistles)
WHAT ARE WE THROWING DOWN?
WHOLE MEMPHIS SHOULDER.
WE'RE GONNA
PREPARE THAT SHOULDER
AND GET RID
OF SOME OF THAT FAT.
ALLOW A LITTLE MEAT TO SHINE
THROUGH AND MAKE NICE BARK.
BARK IS A CRUST. BARK IS
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS.
WE'RE GONNA USE
AN INJECTION MARINADE
WITH ITALIAN SALAD DRESSING.
I'M GONNA RESERVE THE PEPPER
AND GARLIC IN APPLE JUICE,
AND THEN I'LL WHISK IN SOME
OF THAT MAGIC HONKY TONK RUB.
TAKE THAT MIXTURE.
TIME TO INJECT OUR SHOULDER.
WITH THE OIL
IN THE SALAD DRESSING,
THE FIRE GET HOT ENOUGH
THAT IT ACTUALLY COOKS THE PORK
FROM THE INSIDE OUT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA USE
OUR MUSTARD PAINT MIXTURE,
ABOUT EQUAL PARTS
MUSTARD AND BEER.
A LITTLE PEPPER,
WE GOT A LITTLE SALT.
ADD THAT PEPPERS
AND GARLIC.
THIS KIND OF FEELS LIKE
I'M IN THE MAD SCIENTIST LAB.
AND THEN A LOT,
NICE CONSISTENCY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
SPRINKLE SOME RUB.
YOU'RE NOT
GONNA RUB THAT IN.
THE MUSTARD'S GONNA MAKE
IT STICK. IT'S READY TO GO IN.
THAT IS GREAT-LOOKING, MAN.
215 DEGREES, 17 HOURS.
AND THAT TOOK THIRD PLACE
IN MEMPHIS IN MAY?
YES, SIR.
I CAN'T WAIT.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
(whistles)
CLEAN BONE, THAT'S IT. THAT'S
THE SIGN RIGHT THERE, BABY.
AHH, GORGEOUS.
GOT A NICE SMOKE RING.
SEE THAT PENETRATION
OF THE SMOKE? A LITTLE MORE RUB.
THAT'S A WINNER. THAT BARBECUE'S
GOT GOOD SMOKE ON IT.
LOOK AT THAT PIECE RIGHT THERE--
NICE BARK ON THE TOP.
YOU CAN TELL THE PEOPLE
THAT LOVE BARBECUE,
YOU GOTTA EAT IT
WITH YOUR HANDS.
MMM. OH, DUDE, I DIG IT.
THE SMOKE
GIVES IT THE FLAVOR.
FALLS APART
WITHOUT BEING SUPER WET
OR EXTRA DRY.
NOW WHAT ARE YOU
MAULING OVER THERE?
OH, I'VE GOT
THE PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
YOU KNOW IT'S MONEY.
IS THIS HOW BIG
THE SANDWICH IS HERE?
10-OUNCE SANDWICH.
NOW, LISTEN, PAUL BUNION.
NOW WHAT SAUCE THAT YOU HAVE
ARE WE GONNA PUT ON THIS?
I LIKE THE CAROLINA MUSTARD
GARLIC, THE MEMPHIS VINEGAR.
MMM, THE VINEGAR SIDE...
FOR THE SANDWICH, YOU GOTTA
DO THE MEMPHIS VINEGAR.
TO ME IT JUST GOES
HAND IN HAND.
THE PORK JUST BY ITSELF--
TRY IT WITH THAT MUSTARD SAUCE,
THAT IS ON POINT.
IT WAS ACTUALLY
VERY GOOD ON THE MEAT.
THE VINEGAR,
IT'S A LITTLE MORE TART.
AND THERE'S
A SWEET ONE, TOO.
MMM, I LOVE HAVING THREE
DIFFERENT SAUCES TO CHOOSE FROM.
ONE OF EACH.
THE SAUCE IS PHENOMENAL--
ALL OF THEM.
TIP?
IT SEEMS LIKE
EVERYTHING HERE--
THE MEAT, THE SAUCES--THERE'S
A REAL ATTENTION TO DETAIL.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
THE WAY WILLIE DOES IT.
IT'S A REALLY DIFFERENT
BARBECUE EXPERIENCE FOR CHICAGO.
ESPECIALLY THE RIBS.
CHICAGO HAS A TRADITION OF RIBS
THAT ARE COVERED WITH SAUCE.
THESE ARE DRY-RUBBED.
HONKY-TONKIN' TASTY.
FROM ST. LOUIS SPARES
TO BABY BACKS
TO THE BIG BEEF
SHORT RIBS.
MMM.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE SAME HONKY TONK RUB
THAT WE USE
FOR THE PORK.
I ADD A LITTLE BIT
MORE BLACK PEPPER,
'CAUSE THAT BEEF
HAS A NICE RICH FLAVOR.
AND SOME
WHITE PEPPER ALSO.
THAT'LL LIVEN IT UP.
I'M GONNA PREPARE
THE BEEF SHORT RIBS--
TWO RIBS TO A PORTION.
AND YOU
COOK 'EM TOGETHER
SO YOU KEEP AS MUCH
MOISTURE AS YOU CAN.
AND WE'RE GONNA
APPLY THE RUB.
THEY JUST NEED A LIGHT COATING.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
6 1/2 HOURS
AT THAT 210, 215?
YEP.
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT THING.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE, ALL
THE FLAVOR COMING OUT OF THAT.
AWESOME. BIG SMOKE RING.
OHH, NOW THAT'S A CROSS BETWEEN
A BRISKET AND A BEEF RIB.
IT'S LIKE BRISKET
ON A STICK.
VERY TENDER, VERY MOIST.
I LOVE THE DRY RUB.
CAN YOU FINISH IT?
I'M ABOUT TO.
FRESH BRISKET OUT.
THE MEAT
WAS REALLY GOOD.
SAMPLER UP.
THE BEST. LOVE IT.
WHY NOT?
(Guy) YOU LOVE THIS,
DON'T YOU?
I DO. I'M DOIN'
WHAT I WANT TO DO RIGHT NOW.
I GET TO WORK WITH PEOPLE
AND FOOD AND PEOPLE HAVING FUN.
AND HERE IT IS.
YEAH, YOU KNOW IT.
NEXT UP...
GOOD WILD MUSHROOMS,
REALLY GOOD FETA CHEESE.
IDAHO...
ONE OF OUR
FAVORITE PLACES TO EAT.
WHERE THEY GOT
THEIR OWN TAKE ON PIZZA.
HE MAKES HIS
ELK SAUSAGE FROM SCRATCH.
MMM, THAT'S
A PERFECT COMBO.
YOU KNOW, I RUN INTO
THE MOST INTERESTING PLACES
HERE ON TRIPLE "D."
AND TODAY'S TOPIC
IS THE OLD ADAGE
OF DON'T JUDGE A BOOK
BY ITS COVER,
OR MAYBE
I SHOULD JUST CALL IT
DON'T JUDGE A PIZZA
BY ITS NAME.
I'M AT PIZZALCHIK
HERE IN BOISE, IDAHO.
NOW THE NAME MAY BE CRAZY,
BUT THAT'S ONLY
BECAUSE THE FOOD IS INSANE.
LET'S KICK
THESE PIZZAS OUT FIRST.
YES, SIR.
WE HAVE
THE FUNGUS AMUNGUS.
GOOD WILD MUSHROOMS,
REALLY GOOD FETA CHEESE.
WE GOT A SMALL
CHICKEN SALAD FOR YA.
THANK YOU.
ROAST CHICKEN,
THERE'S NO COMPARISON.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THIS NAME, PIZZALCHIK?
THAT'S WHY DIDN'T
STOP HERE THE FIRST TIME.
IT WOULDN'T MATTER WHAT I
CALLED MYSELF. IT'S IN THE FOOD.
PIZZA, SALAD AND CHICKEN--
PIZZALCHIK. SWITCH IT UP.
A UNIQUE TWIST
FOR A CULINARY GRAD...
HOW MUCH PIE WE GOT?
WHO STARTED OUT IN THE HIGH-END
SIDE OF THE BUSINESS.
I JUST GOT TIRED OF THE WHITE
TABLECLOTH, RED NAPKIN SCENE.
I WANTED TO DO SOMETHING
THAT'S FUN, LAID-BACK,
GOOD-QUALITY FOOD.
WITH HIS FAMILY.
SO CHEF BRAD BREAKELL OPENED
THIS PLACE WITH HIS WIFE JUDY.
WHAT TABLE
IS THAT, SAL?
AND GAVE
HIS SON MONTANA
A CRASH COURSE
IN THROWING DOUGH.
IT'S KINDA LIKE YOU GET THIS
GOURMET MEAL ON A PIZZA CRUST.
HAND-TOSSED AND HANDMADE...
HE MAKES HIS
ELK SAUSAGE FROM SCRATCH.
FOR ONE OF THEIR
MOST POPULAR PIES.
THE WILD FOREST MIST.
WITH THAT SAUSAGE
AND PEPPERS AND WILD MUSHROOMS.
MMM.
WILD MUSHROOMS.
IT'S MY OWN
KIND OF REDUCTION--
GARLIC, SHALLOTS,
FRESH HERBS, RED WINE, CREAM.
WE FINISH THE DISH--
LEMON JUICE, SALT AND PEPPER.
OHH.
IS THAT WORKIN' FOR YA?
BROTHER, THAT'S
BEYOND WORKING FOR ME.
COOL.
NOW WE HAVE TO
MAKE THE SAUSAGE.
AND THIS IS FRESH
GROUND ELK MEAT, LOCAL.
REALLY RICH AND LEAN.
ALL RIGHT.
I SEE SOME FAT.
I DON'T WANT TO DESTROY
THE FLAVOR OF THE ELK,
SO I USE A SUET.
I LIKE IT.
TURN ON MY
LITTLE GRINDER.
5 POUNDS OF ELK, AND THERE'S
2 1/2 POUNDS OF FAT.
NOT CUTTIN' IT
WITH ANY BEEF.
NO.
NICE. (whistles)
THIS ALL GOES
INTO OUR SAUSAGE--
THYME,
FRESH RED PEPPER.
YOU HAVE GOT TO BE
KIDDING ME. THAT MUCH?
YEAH. PAPRIKA.
OKAY.
LIKE TO GRIND
OUR OWN PEPPERCORNS.
I DIG IT.
FENNEL SEED, OREGANO.
AND SOME
OF THE HIMALAYAN SEA SALT?
YES. WE ADD
A LITTLE WINE,
GARLIC AND THEN
WE KICK IT UP WITH THIS--
HABANEROS, SERRANOS, ANAHEIM,
PASILLA PEPPERS, JALAPEÑO.
JALAPEÑO. THESE ONES
ARE OUT OF MY GREENHOUSE.
ROASTED 'EM
AND THEN PURéE 'EM.
WE ALSO PUT
SOME ROASTED GARLIC IN HERE
AND SOME MORE RED WINE.
THAT MAGICAL MIXTURE
LOOKS LIKE IT MIGHT BE
A LITTLE BIT
ON THE HOT SIDE.
IT'S EXTREME HOT.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
EXTREME HEAT.
WE'RE GONNA
PUT THAT IN HERE?
WE'RE GONNA GO EASY.
MAN, THAT IS
INTENSE FLAVOR.
LET THIS KINDA--ALL THE FLAVORS
MINGLE FOR 24 HOURS.
ROLL IT, BAKE IT--
14 MINUTES?
YEP.
CANNOT WAIT TO TRY IT,
AND THAT'LL MAKE THE PIZZA.
ACTUALLY,
MONTANA'S DOING THAT.
MY 12-YEAR-OLD SON CAN SPIN
PIZZA LIKE NOBODY'S BUSINESS.
WHOO-HOO.
SO HOW DID YOU START?
THROWING A TOWEL.
OKAY, LET'S SEE THIS.
WOW.
STAND BACK,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
I LIKE THE WAY
IT'S LOOKING.
GENTLE HAND THAT
DOESN'T TEAR THROUGH IT.
PIZZA KILLERS RIGHT THERE.
GIVE A LITTLE EXTRA PUSH.
OKAY, WILD FOREST MIST.
THE SAUSAGE, NOW WE GET
THE MUSHROOMS ON.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA TAKE TO COOK?
AROUND SEVEN
TO EIGHT MINUTES.
YOU READY?
YEAH.
THAT'S IT, HUH? MMM.
THAT'S FANTASTIC. GOOD-LOOKING
CRUST ON THE BOTTOM.
YOU, MY FRIEND, ROCK ON.
THANK YOU.
MMM, THE SAUSAGE,
SOME OF THAT HEAT
MELTS INTO THAT CHEESE,
BUT THE MUSHROOM
GOES SO INCREDIBLY WELL.
THAT'S A PERFECT COMBO.
FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU. MONTANA,
GO DOWN THE LEFT SIDE.
THE CRUST IS OUTSTANDING.
IT'S ALL HAND-THROWN.
THE FLAVORS ARE MARVELOUS.
THE JALAPEÑO, POTATO.
GARLIC, CHICKEN, PINEAPPLE.
HE HAS NO PROBLEM
MIXING IT TOGETHER.
MMM.
OR PUTTING A FAVORITE CUSTOMER
REQUEST ON THE MENU,
LIKE THE GREAT SALMON CAPER.
WHAT DO WE GOT GOING?
WE'RE GONNA BUTCHER
A SALMON AND SMOKE IT.
SO YOU JUST RIDING
RIGHT ALONG THAT BACKBONE.
JUST GOING
FOR THE FEEL.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT
OUR SALMON FILLET.
THIS IS A GREAT BRINE BLEND.
THIS IS NOT MY MIX.
I DO ADD MY OWN MAGIC
TO IT, THOUGH.
JALAPEÑOS?
MY SMOKED JALAPEÑO.
THIS IS TOASTED WHOLE CUMIN.
SHUT HER DOWN.
WE'LL NOW ADD ICE.
OH, MAN, THAT'S STRONG.
YEAH, FIRST
IT'LL GET YA.
WE PLACE THE SALMON
FLESH-SIDE DOWN.
HOW LONG
DO WE BRINE IT FOR?
24 HOURS, THEN OUT
TO MY LITTLE BIG CHIEF SMOKER,
WHICH IS...
OOH, WHERE?
IN THE ALLEY.
YOU HAVE
A $50,000 PIZZA OVEN
AND A $75
BIG CHIEF SMOKER.
OKAY.
BUT IT WORKS.
WE'LL JUST PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS ON THE PIZZA
AND THEN I'LL
TAKE THE REST HOME.
THIS IS
A WHITE CRUST PIZZA.
A LITTLE
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
ROASTED GARLIC PASTE,
A 50/50 BLEND
OF PROVOLONE, MOZZARELLA.
LET ME GET THAT
OUT OF THE WAY.
THAT IS OUTSTANDING.
AND THEN HOUSE-PICKLED
ARTICHOKE HEARTS.
SUPER MEGA THIN.
AND CAPERS, A LITTLE
RED ONION ON THERE,
LIGHT DUST OF PARMESAN CHEESE,
INTO THE OVEN.
THAT'S THE LANDING ZONE, YOU
TURN IT INTO THE FINISHING ZONE.
THIS ONE WE FINISH OFF
WITH SOME FRESH BASIL.
OH, MAN. THAT'S AWESOME.
OUT OF BOUNDS. MMM!
AMAZING, REALLY DYNAMITE.
WHAT HE DOES WITH HIS SALMON--
IT'S SO TENDER. MMM.
IT'S JUST REAL TASTY.
BECAUSE IT'S SO FRESH.
IT'S FRESH FOOD.
IT'S UNUSUAL.
EVEN SOMETHING SIMPLE
LIKE A SALAD.
TABLE 23.
SALAD HAS GOTTA BE
ONE OF THE MOST UNIQUE THINGS
I THINK THEY HAVE HERE.
TEQUILA LIME PRAWN SALAD--
IT'S GREAT.
MY FAVORITE IS
THE SMOKED SALMON SALAD.
OKAY, WE GOT PIZZA,
WE GOT SALAD,
BUT IT IS PIZZAL CHIK.
HIS CHICKEN IS TO DIE.
THE REST OF THE MENU
WHEN WE COME BACK.
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
CHICKEN DINNER.
YOU GOT SPECIALS COVERED?
AT PIZZALCHIK
IN BOISE, IDAHO...
GARLIC, GARLIC,
ROASTED GARLIC.
CHEF BRAD BREAKELL'S GOT HIS
OWN VERSION OF A HAT TRICK.
PIZZA, SALAD AND CHICKEN.
THEIR PIZZA'S DELICIOUS.
SALAD'S DON'T LOOK LIKE
WHAT YOU EXPECT.
LET ME ASK YOU
ABOUT THE CHICKEN--
WHO'S HAD SOME
OF THE ROAST--
(oohing)
THE CHICKENS THAT HE ROASTS
JUST COME OUT PHENOMENALLY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT
ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
OUR GARLIC SHROOM CHICKEN.
SO A LITTLE OREGANO, SOME SAGE,
SOME THYME AND SOME BASIL.
YES.
AND WHERE ARE YOU
GETTING THESE FRESH HERBS?
I DO HAVE A GREENHOUSE
AT MY HOUSE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OH, YEAH, I ONLY USE FRESH HERBS
AS MUCH AS I POSSIBLY CAN.
AND MY SECRET INGREDIENT
OVER HERE.
KAFIR?
YES.
THANK YOU. I'M OUT.
(laughs)
I TAKE THE DRIED MUSHROOMS,
THROW 'EM IN THERE
AND THEN THE GARLIC, A LITTLE
SALT, FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
ONLY WAY
TO ROLL, BABY.
AND I TAKE THIS IS ALL GOING
UNDER THE SKIN?
YES, SIR.
NICE.
I LIKE TO GET A LITTLE HERB
PINCH BETWEEN MY FINGERS
'CAUSE I CAN TRANSPORT
THE HERBS ALL THE WAY UP,
AND THEN I JUST
KIND OF WORK 'EM AROUND.
I AM RIPPING
THIS OFF FOR SURE.
THE FINGER PUNT
AND THE PULL, NICE DISMOUNT.
I SAVE SOME FOR STUFFING
IN THE CAVITY OF THE BIRD.
UNDER THE RIB RIGHT HERE...
UH-HUH.
SO YOU'RE GONNA
POP A LITTLE HOLE...
THIS IS GONNA
BE INTERESTING.
PULL BACK...
NO.
AND TUCK,
WE HAVE JAMMED THE LEGS
THROUGH THE SIDES.
NOW WHAT WILL HAPPEN--WE'LL COOK
IT ON THE MOON SURFACE?
PAN SPRAYED
WITH CANOLA OIL.
WOULD YOU DO ME THE HONOR
OF STICKING IT IN THE OVEN?
AIM RIGHT THERE. WE GOTTA
WATCH THAT AND TURN IT.
TURN IT, TURN IT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A BEAUTY. I USUALLY DEGLAZE
THE PAN WITH SOME WHITE WINE.
AND THEN WHEN WE SERVE OUR
CHICKEN, WE JUST KINDA GO DOWN
THE BACKBONE, POP IT,
DOWN ALONG THE SIDES
AND THEN POUR
A LITTLE JUICE ON THEM.
LET'S TRY
THIS BAD BOY. MMM.
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED
TO SELL HERE, BUDDY.
IT'S PERFECTLY
COOKED. MMM.
BUT THIS MUSHROOM
THAT YOU PUT IN WITH
MAGIC FINGERS MAKES IT.
THAT'S GREAT.
IT'S A WINNER?
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
CHICKEN DINNER.
I'D DO THIS ALL DAY LONG. IT'S
RIDICULOUS. NICE JOB, "B-RAD."
THIS CHICKEN IS TO DIE.
MOIST, TENDER, WELL DONE,
JUST PHENOMENALLY GOOD.
JUST TO COME IN AND SMELL IT
IS LIKE I'M FULL.
SO SMELL-A-VISION
IS ALIVE AND WELL.
IN THIS STORE IT IS.
I'M GOING,
MAN, I'M GOING.
THEY HAVE SUCH GOOD FOOD,
IT'S HARD TO STAY AWAY.
COMING IN.
ONE OF OUR
FAVORITE PLACES TO EAT.
PERFECT. IT'S A PASSION
WITHOUT A DOUBT.
DON'T GET FOOLED BY
THE FUNNY CHICKEN OUT FRONT.
THIS GUY'S LEGIT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."