HI, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
FRENCH MEAT PIE.
THIS TRIP...
THE FOOD
HAS NEVER CHANGED.
LEGACY.
WHERE DID THE RECIPES COME FROM?
YOUR MOM GOT 'EM FROM...
HER MOTHER.
IN BUFFALO...
BARBECUE MEAT LOAF.
UPSCALE VERSION
OF THE OLD CLASSIC.
THE '50s DINER...
BLUEBERRY PANCAKES!
REBORN.
EVERYTHING
IS REALLY HOMEMADE.
WITH SCRATCH COOKIN'...
ITALIAN SAUSAGE!
GONE WILD.
WOW. YOU MAKE
YOUR OWN HAM?
MAKE OUR OWN HAM.
MM-HMM.
OHH.
IN OHIO...
PEPPERONI.
IT'S THE BEST PIZZA
IN TOWN.
A LOCAL LEGEND...
OKAY, READY FOR THE OVEN.
DOIN' OLD-TIME ITALIAN.
(Italian accent) PIZZA.
YOU GOTTA HAVE THE PIE.
"PIZ-ZA."
FOR MORE
THAN HALF A CENTURY.
BETTER THAN
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER'S.
OH, JEEZ, STOP.
AND IN
ATTLEBORO, MASSACHUSETTS...
YEAH, I GOT
A FISHERMAN'S STEW HERE.
A THIRD-GENERATION JOINT...
THIS FOOD HAS BEEN COOKED
WITH LOVE.
NEW ENGLAND BOILED DINNER.
STILL IN THE SAME FAMILY
AFTER 98 YEARS.
THIS IS THE WAY
WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IT.
GOOD OLD SCHOOL.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM,
BUFFALO, NEW YORK,
UH, ABOUT 5 MILES NORTHEAST
OF LAKE ERIE,
AT A JOINT
THAT WAS ONCE A DINER
AND THEN CHANGED
INTO A CHINESE RESTAURANT,
WELL, THEN TRANSPLANTED
FROM PENNSYLVANIA
AND THEN TURNED BACK
INTO A DINER.
AND GUESS WHAT? THAT'S
NOT EVEN THE AMAZING PART.
THESE GUYS,
THEY'RE CURING THEIR OWN HAM,
THEY'RE CORNING THEIR OWN BEEF,
AND THEY'RE SMOKING
THEIR OWN BACON.
THIS IS
LAKE EFFECT DINER.
PULLED PORK! THE REAL DEAL.
RED EYE GRAVY GOING DOWN.
KIND OF UNIQUE IN BUFFALO.
BARBECUE MEAT LOAF.
AN UPSCALE VERSION
OF THE OLD CLASSIC.
BLUEBERRY PANCAKES!
YOU CAN REALLY
TASTE THE DIFFERENCE.
ARE THERE A LOT
OF DINERS IN BUFFALO?
UH, NOT TOO MANY.
NO, NOT TOO MANY.
NOT LIKE THIS.
A '50s LEGACY...
TWO SUNSHINES IN A GLASS.
THAT TUCKER CURTIN...
ITALIAN SAUSAGE!
AND HIS WIFE ERIN
BROUGHT BACK TO LIFE.
TABLE 24.
WE WENT LOOKING FOR
THE DINER CAR,
AND WE WERE ABLE
TO RESURRECT IT
AND PUT IT BACK
INTO SERVICE AGAIN.
NOW THIS JOINT IS SMOKIN'
FOR REAL.
READY TO ROCK 'N' ROLL.
EVERYTHING FROM TURKEY
TO BACON...
OH, IT'S SO GOOD.
TO HAM.
SO A BONELESS PORK LEG,
AND YOU'RE
GONNA MAKE YOUR OWN--
GONNA MAKE OUR OWN HAM.
I DON'T THINK ON TRIPLE "D" YET
WE'VE SEEN ANYBODY MAKE A HAM.
THIS IS--THIS IS
OLD-SCHOOL CURING.
WE'LL START
WITH OUR BRINE, OKAY.
ABOUT A GALLON OF WATER,
SOME DRIED CLOVES HERE,
BLACK PEPPERCORNS...
DRY MUSTARD.
LOTS OF DRY MUSTARD,
LIGHT BROWN SUGAR,
MADE RIGHT HERE
IN BUFFALO, NEW YORK.
MAPLE SYRUP...
ATTABOY.
SODIUM NITRATE HERE...
OFFERS NICE COLOR.
AND THEN KOSHER SALT.
OKAY. BRING THAT
TO A LITTLE SIMMER?
YES, WE'RE GONNA GET THAT
INTO A RUMBLING BOIL.
THEN WE'LL CUT OUR HAM IN HALF,
POUR THAT COOLED BRINE ON TOP,
AND THAT'S
A 12-, 14-DAY PROCESS.
AND THEN IT'LL GO
TO THE SMOKER?
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS.
WE'LL ALSO
SLOW-SMOKE THE BONES
THAT WE'LL USE IN THE STOCK
FOR OUR RED-EYE GRAVY.
SMOKE THOSE
OVER MESQUITE CHARCOAL,
AND WE ALSO BURN
APPLE AND HICKORY WOODS.
WOW.
SUGARS ARE STARTING
TO CARAMELIZE UP ON 'EM.
LOOK AT THIS. JUST TAKE
A LITTLE LOOKY LOU AT THAT.
ISN'T THAT BEAUTIFUL?
IT'S GOT THAT REAL MAPLE--
DON'T TALK
IN THE MIDDLE OF IT, JUST--
OHH, AND THIS IS ALL FOR
A BREAKFAST ITEM ON A MENU?
CORRECT.
A BREAKFAST ITEM.
ONE ITEM.
SO NOW WE TAKE 'EM,
POP 'EM IN THE OVEN,
BRINGING UP TO ABOUT 145,
FINISH THE COOKING PROCESS,
(Guy) TAKE 'EM OUT.
WE GOT OUR BONES.
THEY'RE ALL SMOKED OFF.
I'VE GOT THE FAT
NICELY OUT OF 'EM.
AND NOW I'M GONNA DUMP
THE PAN JUICES IN THERE.
A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
CARROTS, CELERY AND ONION.
DIG IT.
BLACK PEPPERCORN.
WE ARE GONNA
BE STRAINING THIS.
YES, WE ARE. SOME KOSHER SALT,
FRANK'S HOT SAUCE.
WOW.
THIS IS THE SECRET
TO GOOD WINGS.
IT'S ALSO THE SECRET
TO GOOD RED-EYE GRAVY.
BRINDLE OF FRESH THYME,
ADD SOME COFFEE TO IT.
NOW HOW LONG WILL THIS
SIT THERE AND SIMMER?
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS.
STRAIN IT, AND THEN IT'LL BE
READY TO SERVE WITH THE HAM.
CORRECT.
GOT OUR HAM RIGHT HERE.
SLICE 'EM UP.
GET THAT GOING ON THE FLATTOP
WITH EGGS AND HOME FRIES.
EGG, EGG, BABY.
A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR RED-EYE GRAVY HERE.
LET ME GET THESE EGGS,
SOME OF OUR HOME FRIES,
GET OUR HAM ON THERE, TOO.
A LITTLE MORE RED-EYE GRAVY.
I KINDA HOPED
YOU WERE GONNA SAY THAT.
MMM, THERE'S THIS VERY
FLAVORFUL, TENDER HAM FOR SURE.
OHH. I'D LIKE A SIDE
OF HAM WITH SOME HAM.
BEING RAISED
EATING RED-EYE GRAVY,
I'VE SEEN A LOT
OF DIFFERENT VARIATIONS.
I DO THINK I WOULD LIKE TO HAVE
A CUP OF RED-EYE GRAVY TO CHUG.
MMM. AWESOME, BROTHER.
NICE JOB.
ORDER UP.
HAM RED-EYE GRAVY!
VERY GOOD, VERY MOIST.
EVERYTHING IS REALLY FRESH,
REALLY HOMEMADE.
95% OF THE THINGS
YOU GUYS SERVE, YOU MAKE...
ABSOLUTELY.
FROM SCRATCH.
ABSOLUTELY. ORDER UP!
OUR CUSTOMERS DESERVE THE BEST.
IF WE HAVE THE ABILITY
TO PROVIDE THAT QUALITY FOOD,
IT'S OUR JOB TO DO IT.
FAVORITES LIKE
STUFFED POTATO PANCAKES...
MMM.
HOMEMADE SAUSAGE...
MM-HMM.
MM-HMM?
OHH.
AND THIS ONE.
FRESH HADDOCK,
GOING ITALIAN STYLE.
YOU A BIG HADDOCK FAN?
I AM. THIS IS
EXACTLY THE WAY I LIKE IT.
THE TOP OF IT HAS
LIKE A BRUSCHETTA.
SO WHAT
ARE WE MAKING NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME BALSAMIC VINAIGRETTE,
WHICH WE'RE GONNA ADD
TO OUR BRUSCHETTA.
AND WE USE THAT
ON OUR ITALIAN FISH.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET STARTED.
WHAT DO WE GOT?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME
FRESH THYME, PUT THAT IN THERE,
ROSEMARY,
A LITTLE DIJON MUSTARD,
BALSAMIC VINEGAR.
WE'RE GONNA DUMP THE REST OF
THAT BALSAMIC VINEGAR IN THERE.
SLOWLY DRIZZLE IN
OUR OLIVE OIL,
VEGETABLE OIL.
BECAUSE YOU CAN CUT IT.
IT DOESN'T
HAVE TO BE ALL--
YEAH, YOU DON'T
WANT TOO MUCH OLIVE.
IT'S TOO PUNGENT.
A LITTLE PEPPER.
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
IT'S LIKE MAKING AN ITALIAN
MILKSHAKE FOR A SALAD.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW MUCH
THAT TIGHTENED UP?
AND THAT WAS JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF MUSTARD THAT DID THAT.
PRETTY TASTY.
I'LL TAKE THAT ANY DAY.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL SET THAT ASIDE..
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'LL START DOING
SOME BRUSCHETTA, ALL RIGHT?
DIG IT. (whistles)
WE'RE GONNA USE
THE TOMATO KING ON THE TOMATOES
TO CORE THESE OUT.
WELL, YOU JUST DO THAT.
I WANT TO STICK IT IN
AND MAKE IT GO.
YOU WANT TO STICK IT?
HERE, PUT TWO OF 'EM.
BUT GO SLOW WITH IT,
NICE AND STEADY.
YOU DON'T WANT TO JUST PUSH IT
THROUGH TOO QUICKLY,
'CAUSE YOU'LL END UP
WITH FRENCH FRIES.
IT'S NICE, HUH?
LOOK AT WHAT I MADE.
YOU DID A NICE JOB.
YOU MIGHT BE ABLE TO FIND
SOME WORK--WORK FOR YOURSELF.
WELL, YOU KNOW.
WE'LL TAKE SOME FRESH BASIL,
SOME ONION, CHOPPED GARLIC,
LITTLE BALSAMIC, A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER TO TASTE.
HAVE ALL THEIR ALBUMS.
SO THAT'S GONNA BE THE TOPPING
ON TOP OF THE ITALIAN HADDOCK.
YES.
WHERE ARE WE GONNA GO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA START THIS OFF
WITH A LITTLE GARLIC BUTTER.
SEAR A PIECE OF FISH
ON THE FLATTOP.
WE'RE GONNA DO SOME
GRIDDLE MAC AND CHEESE HERE.
MMM.
I HAVE SOME STEAMED BROCCOLI.
THEN I TAKE SOME FRESH LEMONS
AND SQUEEZE 'EM ON TOP.
FLIP OUR FISH HERE.
THERE WE ARE.
THAT LOOKS NICE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME
OF OUR BRUSCHETTA PRODUCT.
LITTLE WHITE WINE TO THAT.
MAC AND CHEESE
SHOULD BE COMING AROUND,
STEAMED BROCCOLI,
MARINARA TO LAY IT IN.
TAKE OUR FISH,
OUR BRUSCHETTA.
LOOK AT THAT.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU FIND
IN EVERY DINER, RIGHT?
MMM. THAT'S GOT GREAT TEXTURE.
THE FISH IS MEGA-TENDER.
YOU GOT THE FRESH TOMATO
WITH THE BRUSCHETTA MIX. MMM.
GRIDDLE MAC AND CHEESE--
I'M A FAN OF THE FACT THAT
YOU GUYS MAKE EVERYTHING FROM
SCRATCH, BUT YOU KEEP IT SIMPLE.
WAY TO GO, CHEF. FANTASTIC.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
ITALIAN FISH,
MAC AND CHEESE.
IT'S REALLY JUICY.
AND THE MAC AND CHEESE...
ON THE FLATTOP
WITH THE CRUNCHY CRUNCH.
YES. YEAH.
COME ON NOW.
YEAH.
(Tucker) ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
CLASSIC DINER FEEL BUT IT TASTES
MORE LIKE A HOME-COOKED MEAL.
(Tucker) ORDER UP!
AND THIS IS REAL DEAL.
YEAH.
QUALIFIED.
HERE'S MY STAMP OF APPROVAL.
READY? THAT'S IT.
WE MAKE PEOPLE HAPPY EVERY DAY,
AND WE DO IT ONE MEAL AT A TIME.
B.L.T.
AND WE'RE GONNA
KEEP ON DOING IT.
BEEF ON WECK!
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
AND YOU'RE STILL DOING IT
WITH SMILES ON YOUR FACE,
AND YOU'RE STILL MARRIED.
YEAH.
UP NEXT WE'RE HEADING
TO OHIO...
BEST PIZZA I HAVE EVER HAD.
SHELLS AND...
SHELLS AND MEATBALLS.
FOR ITALIAN CLASSICS...
GRANDMA GERACI'S
FAMOUS MEATBALLS.
NEAR CLEVELAND.
MMM.
THAT'S ONE OF THE MOST TENDER
MEATBALLS I'VE EVER TRIED.
THANKS.
WHEN I WAS A KID,
ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS I'D ASK
MY MOM IN THE MORNING
IS "WHAT'S FOR DINNER?"
I MEAN, I ASKED HER
WHAT'S FOR DINNER SO MUCH
IT DROVE HER NUTS,
DROVE HER NUTS TO THE POINT
WHERE SHE MADE A RULE.
I WASN'T ALLOWED TO ASK "WHAT'S
FOR DINNER?" UNTIL AFTER LUNCH.
NOW WHAT WAS I HOPING?
WELL, JUST LIKE ANY KID, I WAS
HOPING SHE WAS GONNA SAY PIZZA.
NOW USUALLY IT WASN'T PIZZA,
SO THAT'S WHY HERE ON TRIPLE "D"
EVERY TIME I GET A CHANCE
TO TRY THE PIE I AM THERE.
I'M ON THE EAST SIDE
OF CLEVELAND
TO HIT GERACI'S
AND TRY THEIR 53-YEAR TRADITION.
PEPPERONI.
THE BEST PIZZA
IN TOWN.
(man) IT'S AMAZING.
REALLY?
YEAH, I LOVE IT.
(woman) SAUSAGE COMING OUT.
EVERYTHING I'VE EVER HAD HERE
IS OUTSTANDING.
SHELLS AND...
SHELLS AND MEATBALLS.
VEAL PARMESAN.
VEAL PARM.
SO HUNGRY FOR IT,
I HAD TO HAVE IT.
REAL DEAL ITALIAN FOOD.
REAL DEAL.
SINCE 1956.
RAVIOLI UP.
WHAT'S TERRIFIC IS THE FOOD
HAS NEVER CHANGED.
SAME OWNERS, TOO...
READY FOR THE OVEN.
MICHAEL GERACI
AND HIS WIFE FRAN.
I HOPE YOU ENJOY
THIS EVENING.
SHE'S 87.
SHE'S 87. HE'S 90.
WOW.
WE'RE STILL HERE,
MY WIFE AND I.
STILL COME IN EVERY DAY.
THEY BOTH COME IN
EVERY DAY.
BUT THESE DAYS DAUGHTER FRAN,
SAME NAME AS HER MOM,
IS DOING THE HEAVY LIFTING...
MEATBALL.
HAVE YOU WORKED HERE
ALL YOUR LIFE?
SINCE I'VE BEEN
2 YEARS OLD,
SINCE THE DAY THEY OPENED.
AND LOADING UP THE PIES
SINCE SHE WAS 11.
YOU'RE UP.
BEST PIZZA I HAVE EVER HAD.
YOU KNOW WHAT I GOT
TO HAVE NOW.
(Italian accent) PIZZA.
YOU GOTTA HAVE THE PIE.
"PIZ-ZA."
SOME PIZZA DOUGH.
(normal voice) WE'RE MAKING
PIZZA DOUGH.
OUR DOUGH IS MADE HOMEMADE
EVERY DAY.
(coughs)
THERE WE GO.
I THINK THIS CAME OFF
THE "U.S.S. ENTERPRISE."
OKAY, A LITTLE SALT...
PROBABLY DID.
LITTLE SUGAR.
ONE CAKE OF YEAST DISSOLVED.
ONE YEAST CAKE.
YEAH.
QUART OF OIL.
JUST REGULAR CANOLA?
LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL
BLENDED IN THERE, TOO.
AND THEN SOME WARM WATER
TO KEEP THE YEAST ALIVE.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE USUALLY MAKE THIS
TWO TO THREE TIMES A DAY.
WHAT?
EACH BATCH MAKES
ABOUT 80 PIZZAS.
THAT'S A LOT OF PIE.
LET THIS MIX.
TEN MINUTES?
YEAH.
AND THEN START HACKING 'EM OFF,
WEIGHING 'EM AND GOING.
GO.
THIS IS MASSIVE.
YEAH.
(accent) IT'S A BRAIN.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL
SOME DOUGH.
WEIGH IT OUT TO 16 OUNCES.
(normal voice) OKAY.
PERFECT.
TURN THE DOUGH IN.
ROLL 'EM IN.
ROLL 'EM IN, TIGHTEN UP
THE BOTTOM. PUT IT ON THE TRAY.
SO THEY PROOF AGAIN
AFTER WE ROLL THEM.
THEN YOU POUND THEM DOWN
JUST TO GET 'EM STARTED,
AND NOW WE GET
TO THIS POINT HERE
WHERE WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME PIZZAS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE PIE.
JUST GENTLY SPREAD IT OUT.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
SEE, EVERYBODY
HAS THEIR OWN STYLE.
I'M INTO... (whistles)
AND I LIKE MY SAUCE
ALL THE WAY TO THE EDGE.
YEAH.
SEE HOW NICE AND CHUNKY
THAT SAUCE IS?
OKAY, SO LET'S RECAP
THIS SAUCE.
YOU SWEAT THE ONIONS,
LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR IN THIS.
AND SALT, OREGANO, BASIL,
STANISLAUS TOMATOES.
DIG IT.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME MOZZARELLA CHEESE,
PART SKIM,
NICE AND CREAMY.
IT'S GREAT.
THIS IS MARGHERITA PEPPERONI.
MMM.
THIS IS THE BEST.
THAT'S GOT GREAT SPICE TO IT.
WE CUT IT REAL THICK.
THIS IS WHAT
OUR CUSTOMERS LOVE.
PEPPERONI FAT THAT
REALLY FLAVORS THE PIE.
RIGHT.
THE TOPPING TO DOUGH RATIO
IS 50-50.
YEAH.
SO WE'RE GONNA COOK 'EM
ON THESE PANS, THOUGH?
YEP. STICK 'EM INTO THE OVEN,
550.
COMING AROUND ME.
WHAT, ARE WE GONNA DANCE NOW?
OKAY, STOP THAT.
GET IN THE OVEN.
HANSEL AND GRETEL OR WHAT?
JUMP IN.
HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA TAKE
TO COOK?
SEVEN, EIGHT MINUTES.
LOOK AT THOSE PIES.
THESE ARE PERFECT.
THAT'S NOT FAT, BABY.
THAT'S FLAVOR.
YOU HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
IN THAT PAN...
YEAH.
SO IT DOESN'T STICK,
BUT IT ALSO KIND OF CREATES THIS
LITTLE BIT OF A FRIED TEXTURE.
YEAH.
THIS THING SOUNDS LIKE
AN ICEBREAKER
ON A SHIP IN ALASKA.
HOT.
I LOVE TO FEEL THE BURN.
MMM. THAT PEPPERONI
IS RIDICULOUS.
IT'S MY DAD'S FAVORITE.
COST IS NOT AN ISSUE
TO MY FATHER
WHEN IT COMES TO THAT PIZZA.
THAT PEPPERONI,
IT'S LIKE GOLD.
IT'S AN INTERESTING
CRUST STYLE,
LITTLE BIT DOUGHY BUT A REAL
NICE HEAVY CRUST ON THE BOTTOM.
I THINK THE WAY I WOULD DESCRIBE
THAT PIE THE BEST
IS TO SAY IT'S REALLY FRESH.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
SMALL PEPPERONI,
EXTRA CHEESE.
NO ONE ELSE HAS PEPPERONI
LIKE THIS.
IT'S DELICIOUS. IT'S ALWAYS
WHERE WE ORDER PIZZA FROM.
PESTO VEGGIE.
(woman) LOOK AT ALL THE TOPPINGS
ON THE PIZZA.
WELL, THIS IS LIKE
THE HOUSE OF TOPPINGS.
YEAH, IT IS.
NOW WHERE DID THE RECIPES
COME FROM, FRAN?
MY MOM.
AND YOUR MOM GOT 'EM FROM?
HER MOTHER.
MORE FETTUCCINE ALFREDO
THAN ONE PERSON CAN EAT.
SERIOUSLY.
VEAL PARM, REAL THIN,
THE WAY WE LIKE IT HERE.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
ANOTHER HOME RUN.
AND ANOTHER THIRD GENERATION
FAMILY FAVORITE...
DO YOU NORMALLY EAT
THE MEATBALLS?
PRETTY MUCH EVERY TIME.
SOMETIMES I JUST GET MEATBALLS
IN A BOWL OF SAUCE.
GRANDMA GERACI'S
FAMOUS MEATBALLS.
WE START WITH 10 POUNDS
OF GROUND BEEF.
MUSH IT UP A LITTLE IT.
5 POUNDS OF GROUND VEAL--MAKES
THIS MEATBALLS NICE AND TENDER.
WHISK UP THESE EGGS.
THERE'S A DOZEN AND A HALF.
OKAY.
DO SOME SALT, PEPPER.
YOU WANT ME TO SPRINKLE IN
THE BREADCRUMBS OR ANYTHING?
THAT'D BE FABULOUS.
WE MAKE OUR BREADCRUMBS
HOMEMADE HERE.
I'M A GOOD BREADCRUMB-ER.
YES, YOU ARE.
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
WE DON'T WANT TO OVERMIX THESE
BECAUSE THEN THEY BECOME TOUGH.
I HAVE A GENTLE TOUCH.
HOW ABOUT SOME OF THAT
GOOD ROMANO CHEESE
THAT'S GONNA GO IN HERE NOW.
OH, YES.
GOOD CHEESE FLAVOR TO THIS.
SMELL THAT?
SO YOU DON'T EVER
GO TO THE GYM DO YOU?
YOU JUST COME HERE AND WORK OUT
AT THE RESTAURANT.
I GO TO THE GYM EVERY NIGHT,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
TURN--LET ME SEE. IS THERE
A CAPE ON THE BACK OF YOU?
OKAY, SUPER FRAN,
WANT SOME AGUA?
LITTLE BIT.
THAT'S GOOD.
NOW HOW MANY MEATBALLS
IS THIS GONNA MAKE US?
I'D SAY 25.
THAT'S THE SIZE
YOU'RE MAKING?
THEY SHRINK UP
IN THE OVEN, SO...
OKAY, A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
IN THE PAN
SO IT DOES A LITTLE BIT
OF STEAMING.
NEVER COVER 'EM.
NO.
WHAT TEMPERATURE ARE
WE GONNA COOK THESE AT?
450.
45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR
TILL THEY'RE NICE AND BROWN.
YEP.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
MEATBALL MADNESS.
YOU CAN EVEN SEE
WHERE THE CHEESE
IS STARTING TO COME OUT
OF SOME OF THESE.
LOOK AT THAT. IT'S NICE
AND PINK, NOT OVERCOOKED.
SEE ALL THE JUICE IN THERE.
SEE SOME OF THAT PARSLEY.
I'M A MEATBALL AFICIONADO,
YOU KNOW THAT.
THAT'S GOOD.
MMM. THAT IS BEYOND TENDER.
THAT'S ONE OF THE MOST TENDER
MEATBALLS I'VE EVER TRIED.
THANKS.
(woman) THEY'RE ACTUALLY BETTER
THAN MY GRANDMOTHER'S.
(Guy) BETTER?
THEY'RE ACTUALLY BETTER THAN
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER'S.
OH, JEEZ,
YOU'RE JUST--STOP.
ONE SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALL.
THE WORLD-FAMOUS
GERACI SAUCE.
ABSOLUTELY.
SAUSAGE COMING IN.
THEY KNOW WHAT
THEY'RE DOING.
ONE MEAT LASAGNA UP.
(woman) WHEN I MOVED
TO CLEVELAND,
EVERYBODY TOLD ME YOU HAVE
TO GO TO GERACI'S,
AND I'VE BEEN COMING EVER SINCE,
AND THAT'S 30 YEARS.
PEPPERONI, DAD.
THAT'S IT.
THANKS.
WHEN DID YOU KIND OF TAKE OVER
THE LEAD POSITION HERE?
I STILL HAVEN'T.
I DON'T HAVE
THE LEAD POSITION.
NEXT STOP...
NEW ENGLAND BOILED DINNER.
MASSACHUSETTS...
MORIN'S IS THE BEST.
FOR COMFORT FOOD...
FRENCH PIE GOING OUT.
DONE THE SAME WAY
FOR ALMOST 100 YEARS.
BEEN DOWN THE ROAD
A FEW TIMES ON THIS ONE.
SO HERE I AM,
40 MILES SOUTH OF BOSTON
IN ATTLEBORO, MASS.,
A TOWN THAT WAS ONCE CONSIDERED
THE JEWELRY MANUFACTURING
CAPITAL OF THE COUNTRY.
NOW AT ONE TIME THERE WAS
36 DINERS IN THIS DOWNTOWN AREA.
TIMES HAVE CHANGED.
35 OF 'EM ARE GONE,
AND 1 IS LEFT STANDING,
A 98-YEAR-OLD
FAMILY-OWNED-AND-OPERATED
ATTLEBORO LANDMARK
THAT'S SERVING NEW ENGLAND-STYLE
COMFORT FOOD.
TIME TO CHECK OUT
MORIN'S HOMETOWN BAR & GRILLE.
TWO MEAT PIES,
MASHED, SIDE OF GRAVY.
FEELS LIKE MOM COOKED IT.
FOOD HAS BEEN COOKED
WITH LOVE.
THANKS, BILLY.
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
DOWN-HOME COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S WHAT WE'RE KNOWN FOR,
IS COMFORT FOOD.
SINCE 1911...
HERE WE GO.
WHEN BILL MORIN'S FAMILY
OPENED THE JOINT.
I AM THE THIRD GENERATION.
MY GRANDFATHER WAS
JEAN BAPTISTE MORIN,
MIGRATED FROM MONTREAL,
ENDED UP RUNNING A DINER.
AFTER COLLEGE AND A FEW YEARS
COOKING IN THE ARMY,
BILL TOOK OVER...
TWO MORE GRILL ORDERS
HERE, MAN.
AND ALMOST 40 YEARS LATER...
(Bill) ALL RIGHT.
HE'S STILL CRANKING OUT
HIS GRANDFATHER'S RECIPES...
TWO FRENCH MEAT PIES.
ESPECIALLY THIS ONE.
EVERY FAMILY HAS THEIR RECIPE,
AND MORIN'S IS THE BEST.
JUST DON'T LET MY MOM KNOW.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
FRENCH MEAT PIE.
BUTTER AND MARGARINE
INTO A HOT PAN.
OKAY, SOME ONION.
WE'RE GONNA LET
THE ONIONS COOK.
I'M GONNA ADD MY GROUND PORK
AND GROUND BEEF.
WE'RE GONNA ALMOST COOK THIS
ALL THE WAY THROUGH
AND THEN BRING IT OVER
TO OUR BUFFALO CHOPPER.
NO BUFFALOS WERE HARMED
IN THE FILMING OF THIS SHOW.
GOOD JOB THERE. WOW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S LOAD UP
THE FOOD CHOPPER.
YOU'RE GONNA DROP
THE HAMMER?
OH, YEAH.
SEE HOW IT CONTINUES TO GET
SMALLER AND SMALLER?
SO THIS IS NOT YOUR FIRST TIME
DOING THIS, IS IT?
BEEN DONE THE ROAD
A FEW TIMES ON THIS ONE.
DICED POTATOES.
BREAK 'EM DOWN
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
YEAH.
JUST A LITTLE...
THAT SOME VODKA?
JUST TAP WATER,
CINNAMON, NUTMEG,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
POWDERED GLOVE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR SALT AND PEPPER,
TOMATO PASTE.
WANT ME TO GET YOU
A SPATULA?
JOHN, HOW ABOUT
BEEF BASE.
OR A...
PIE SERVER.
THAT'LL BE GOOD.
AND THEN JUST
INCORPORATE EVERYTHING.
TOWARDS THE END WE THICKEN IT
WITH A LITTLE INSTANT POTATO
TO BIND IT.
WOW, THAT PIE SERVER,
NEVER KNEW.
OH, YEAH.
WE'LL LET IT COOL DOWN.
THEN WE'LL MIX IT AGAIN,
AND THEN WE'LL GET IT ON THE...
(whistles) DOUGH CRUST.
THERE YOU GO.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE CRUST
FOR THE FRENCH MEAT PIE.
YEAH, WE'LL MAKE THE DOUGH,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA PLATE
THE BOTTOM CRUST.
TAKE THE FILLING, 3 POUNDS.
BRUSH THE EDGE.
YEAH, EGG-WASH THE EDGE.
SO IT'LL STICK.
OH, YEAH.
AND THEN WE PUT THE CRUST
LIKE THIS, CRIMP THE EDGES.
TAKE THE BACK OF A KNIFE,
SLIDE IT RIGHT AROUND.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
EGG-WASH THE TOP.
EGG-WASH AGAIN.
GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE SHEEN
ON THERE.
YOU GOT IT.
ABOUT SIX OR EIGHT HOLES
AND ONE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
SO NOW WHAT TEMPERATURE'S
THE OVEN?
350 DEGREES,
CONVECTION OVEN,
50 MINUTES.
HERE SHE IS.
HEY, LOOK,
WE KNOW THAT TOOL.
OH, YEAH, UNIVERSAL.
THERE YOU GO.
AND THEN A LITTLE
HOUSE-MADE GRAVY.
MMM.
THE MEAT IS DOWN
TO JUST THE RIGHT GRIND
WHERE YOU GET TEXTURE,
BUT IT ALSO MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE PIECRUST IS SUPER
FLAKE-A-LICIOUS.
BUT IT'S THE CINNAMON
AND THEN THE CLOVE
THAT ADD THAT LITTLE--
THAT LITTLE DIVERSE, UM...
I THINK IT'S CALLED ZIP.
IT'S CALLED ZIP.
FRENCH MEAT PIE.
IT'S RICH AND VERY TASTY.
THIS REMINDS ME
OF MY MOTHER'S FOOD.
THANK YOU.
I STILL LIKE TO COOK.
I STILL LIKE TO SEE PEOPLE
COMING IN THAT DOOR.
THERE YOU GO.
THEY ALWAYS HAVE
GREAT SPECIALS.
NEW ENGLAND BOILED DINNER.
CORNED BEEF COMES WITH CABBAGE,
A BUNCH OF VEGETABLES.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THIS IS A PRE-BRINED
CORNED BEEF
THAT NOW WE'RE GONNA GET
INTO SOME BOILING WATER.
IS THAT SALTED WATER?
NO, WE'RE JUST GONNA SEASON IT
WITH A LITTLE MUSTARD.
THAT'S A NEW ONE.
DROP THESE BAD BOYS IN,
ABOUT THREE HOURS?
WE COOK 'EM
ABOUT FOUR AND A HALF.
FOUR AND A HALF.
GOOD-SIZED BRISKET.
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN NOW?
WE'RE GONNA LET IT COOL.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA START
THE VEGGIES.
EXACTLY.
THIS IS JUST TO MAKE
THE VEGETABLES?
YES, IN THEIR OWN POT.
BECAUSE THEY ALL COOK
AT THEIR OWN LEVEL.
YES.
WE'RE GONNA DO
POTATO, TURNIP, BEETS...
CARROTS.
AND THEN...
TONS OF CABBAGE.
CABBAGE.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME
CORNED BEEF BROTH.
EVERYBODY'S GONNA GET
A LITTLE KISS.
A LITTLE ZIP.
OH, ZIP.
GONNA ADD SOME SALT
AND PEPPER.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE FEEDING
CHICKENS WITH THAT.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
BRING 'EM UP TO A BOIL,
AND WE'LL COOK 'EM
TILL THEIR TENDER.
FINISH UP
WITH A LITTLE BUTTER.
OH, BOY.
AND THE CORNED BEEF IS COOLED.
KEEP GOING TILL IT HURTS.
ALL RIGHT.
AND THAT'S ABOUT OUR PORTION.
WE ALWAYS START
WITH THE CABBAGE,
THREE OR FOUR CARROTS,
SAME WAY ON THE TURNIPS,
COUPLE POTATOES,
ABOUT FOUR BEETS,
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
WE HAVE
THE WARM CORNED BEEF
RIGHT ON TOP,
AND JUST A LITTLE PARSLEY,
AND WE'RE THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A PLATTER.
TO NOT LOOK LIKE A ROOKIE HERE,
DO I DO THE TRIPLE NINJA STACK?
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. I LOVE CORNED BEEF
AND CABBAGE.
THE TURNIPS AND THE BEETS ALONG
WITH IT IS A NICE ADDITION.
MMM. IT'S A VERY HEARTY DISH.
AND I THINK IT'S A VERY
TRADITIONAL DISH.
THIS IS THE WAY
WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IT.
IF YOU GET THAT CABBAGE
ANY MORE TENDER, BUDDY,
IT'S GONNA FALL
RIGHT APART ON YOU.
GOOD OLD SCHOOL.
ONE BOILED DINNER HERE.
IT'S DELICIOUS, SERIOUSLY.
EVERYTHING A TRADITIONAL
BOILED DINNER SHOULD BE.
GOOD HOME COOKING.
HAM AND CHEESE OMELET.
REALLY GOOD WHOLESOME
COMFORT FOOD.
(woman) FISHERMAN'S STEW.
IN THE BROTH,
IT'S FABULOUS.
THIS IS THE FISHERMAN'S STEW.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
ANOTHER NEW ENGLAND CLASSIC...
ALL RIGHT.
DONE THE MORIN'S WAY...
SALSA IN FISHERMAN'S STEW.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
SWEET-AND-SOUR PANCAKES.
AT MORIN'S
HOMETOWN BAR & GRILLE
IN ATTLEBORO, MASSACHUSETTS...
OKAY, HERE'S THEIR OMELET.
BILL MORIN'S RUNNING THE PLACE
HIS GRANDFATHER'S WAY,
PURE NEW ENGLAND...
THERE'S YOUR BOILED DINNER,
STACY.
AND THAT'S GOT TO MEAN
FRESH ATLANTIC SEAFOOD.
FISHERMAN'S STEW HERE.
WITH CLAMS AND MUSSELS,
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A FRESH SALSA
TO MAKE OUR FISHERMAN'S STEW.
SALSA IN FISHERMAN'S STEW.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY.
ONIONS.
GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
CANNED CHOPPED TOMATOES.
FRESH TOMATOES.
JALAPEÑOS.
OH, YEAH.
FRESH GARLIC,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
CUMIN.
YOU GOT THAT ONE.
VERY NICE.
VERY GOOD.
CHILI POWDER, BLACK PEPPER,
FRESH CI-LAN-TRO.
DID I SAY THAT CORRECTLY?
CI-LAHN-TRO.
LIKE WHERE YOU GET
YOUR HAIR DONE. SALON.
TOMATO SAUCE,
FRESH LIME JUICE
AND THE SALT.
AND THIS IS GOING
IN A WHAT?
IN A FISHERMAN'S STEW.
ALL RIGHT.
GONNA ADD SOME BUTTER.
I'VE BEEN NOTICING THAT
IN OUR COOKING ADVENTURE
IS THAT IT JUST DOESN'T
LOOK RIGHT.
YOU SEE, I THOUGHT WE COULD JUST
SET HIM UP WITH SOME BLING.
NOW YOU CAN'T EVEN
TELL US APART,
EXCEPT FOR THE SHIRT.
FRESH COD.
AND WE'LL BRING IT
UP TO SPEED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF YOUR NEW SHADES?
EXCELLENT.
WHEN DO I START?
HUH?
WHEN--HE WANTS TO TAKE
THE SHOW OVER.
ARE THESE CHERRYSTONE?
YOU CAN CALL 'EM LITTLENECKS.
YOU CAN CALL 'EM CHERRYSTONES.
WE PUT ABOUT FOUR MUSSELS,
MAKING SURE THEY ARE SHUT.
SO I GOT YOUR TATTOO APPOINTMENT
FOR ABOUT 4:30.
ALL RIGHT. SOUNDS GREAT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR WHITE WINE...
OKAY.
SEAFOOD STOCK,
ORANGE JUICE...
I LIKE WHERE THIS
IS GOING.
LEMON JUICE,
TOMATO SAUCE.
LET ME ADD THE FRESH SALSA
THAT WE HAVE PREPARED,
SALT AND PEPPER,
FRESH BASIL.
MMM.
WE'RE ALMOST GETTING
INTO A CIOPPINO OF SORTS.
COVER IT TO KIND OF HASTEN
THE CLAMS UP A LITTLE BIT HERE.
HOW WE LOOKING?
WE'RE GETTIN' THERE.
THIS HAS HASTENED THINGS.
YES, IT HAS.
TURN IT UP.
I'M GONNA ADD...
COUPLE BAY SCALLOPS.
AND SOME HOME-FRIED POTATOES.
AND, AGAIN, WE'RE JUST GONNA
COVER IT UP AND HASTEN THINGS.
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL THOSE CLAMS,
FRESH NEW ENGLAND SEAFOOD.
STARTING TO WATER
RIGHT BACK THERE.
GARNISH WITH A LITTLE TOMATO,
LITTLE RED ONION, FRESH BASIL.
MMM. OH, IT'S GREAT.
GOT A LITTLE BIT OF KICK TO IT.
NICE FRESH SEAFOOD.
THE BROTH IS DEEP
AND RICH. MMM!
YOU ONLY ARE GONNA NEED
7 OR 12 LOAVES OF BREAD
TO GO WITH THIS.
SOP UP SOME OF THAT BROTH.
OH, MAN.
TENDER, FLAVORFUL AND I REALLY
HAVE TO STOP AT THIS POINT.
MMM!
DOES THAT MEAN
I GET TO KEEP THE GLASSES?
YOU DO. YOU HAVE GRADUATED
TO KEEP THE GLASSES, BROTHER.
AWESOME.
IT'S VERY TANGY.
IT'S VERY ZESTY.
THE TOAST THAT I DIP
INTO THE BROTH IS THE BEST.
LOVE THE TOAST.
FISHERMAN'S STEW,
MEAT PIE.
ALL THE FOOD IS GREAT.
THIS IS DINER LOVE 101.
THIS IS DINER LOVE.
ALL RIGHT,
IT'S ON ITS WAY.
AND IT'S JUST HOMEY,
MAKES ME JUST FEEL NICE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK? MONEY?
MONEY, BILL.
NICE JOB.
DID HE JUST SHOW UP
LOOKING LIKE ME?
SO WAS THAT A MONEY ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU GOT TO GET THIS.