HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
REALLY WELL-KNOWN
THROUGHOUT THE CITY.
NAME THAT COOK.
THERE YOU GO.
IN IDAHO...
SALMON AND POTATO.
WHERE A DUDE NAMED RICK...
PORK CHOPS.
IS WRAPPING SALMON
IN POTATOES...
WOW.
AND PAIRING PORK CHOPS...
MMM.
WITH POLENTA.
THAT'S A TOP CHOP.
IN OKLAHOMA...
IT'S THE BEST PLACE
TO COME IN TOWN.
WHERE NIC IS PILING ON
THE ONION BURGERS...
MMM, ONIONS ARE KILLER.
CRANKIN' OUT...
THERE YOU GO.
THE COMFORT FOOD SPECIALS.
TUESDAY SPECIAL.
PORK CHOPS.
THERE YOU GO.
MEAT LOAF ON FRIDAYS.
THERE'S YOUR CHICKEN.
MMM.
AND IN SEATTLE...
CURRIED CHICKEN.
WHERE PAM IS DOING THE
FAVORITES SHE GREW UP WITH...
PELAU...
IN TRINIDAD...
I LIKE IT. I'M HOOKED.
LIKE CURRIED GOAT...
MMM, EXCELLENT DISH.
AND SOMETHING CALLED PELAU.
MMM, THAT'S DELICIOUS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D"
AS WE CANVAS THE COUNTRY,
WE MAKE ALL KINDS
OF DISCOVERIES
ABOUT PEOPLE AND PLACES
BUT ESPECIALLY ABOUT THE FOOD,
LIKE HERE IN MERIDIAN
OUTSIDE OF BOISE, IDAHO.
AT RICK'S PRESS ROOM,
WHERE FOLKS AROUND HERE TELL ME
THIS DUDE'S GOT A SALMON DISH
THAT IS OFF THE HOOK.
SALMON AND POTATO.
WITH THE POTATOES
SEARED RIGHT ON.
MMM. AWESOME.
HERE WE GO.
IT'S ALWAYS
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
LIKE PORK CHOPS
THE SIZE OF CLEVELAND...
PORK CHOPS.
THIS IS THE LARGEST PORK CHOP
I THINK I'VE EVER EATEN.
AND WINGS
IN A HOMEMADE HOT SAUCE...
MMM.
WITH A DILL
AND CELERY SLAW.
DIFFERENT SPICES,
DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
WOW.
15, 16.
RICK IS
AN AWESOME COOK.
THANK YOU.
THAT'D BE RICK VALENZUELA.
(Rick) WE COOK
EVERYTHING TO ORDER.
STEAMER.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
HOW TO COOK?
TRAINED IN PARIS.
WORKED IN THE BAY AREA,
WORKED IN NEW YORK.
AND THEN SPENT ALMOST
A DECADE IN CORPORATE KITCHENS.
SO YOU DIDN'T GET TO HANG OUT
ON THE LINE ANYMORE?
NOT FOR EIGHT YEARS.
NOT UNTIL HE OPENED THIS JOINT
WITH HIS WIFE JULIE...
ENJOY.
AND DAUGHTER ABBY.
WINGS.
I LIKE TO STAY IN THE BACK,
CREATE DISHES.
LIKE THAT SALMON
AND HASH BROWNS DEAL
HE INVENTED
WHEN HE OPENED THE PLACE.
I LOVE IT. AWESOME.
SOME GOOD-LOOKING SALMON.
TAKE THE SKIN OFF.
OH, THAT'S A KNIFE.
TAKE THE BELLY FAT OFF.
JUST A LITTLE
AROUND THE SIDE, DOC.
THAT'S A NICE
8-OUNCE PORTION.
NOW WE GOTTA
MAKE OUR GLUE.
OUR WHO?
OUR GLUE.
WE GOTTA HAVE SOMETHING
THAT GETS THE POTATOES
TO STICK TO THE SALMON.
SO WE GOT SALMON, SHALLOT.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE FRESH THYME.
GET THAT GOING NICE.
FORTIFY EVERY MORNING
WITH SALMON SHAKES.
SALMON SHAKE AVAILABLE
FOR YOU AT RICK'S.
A LITTLE CREAM,
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER,
GLUE'S DONE.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GLUE ALL OVER,
INTO FRESH HASH BROWNS.
I'M SERIOUSLY
AMAZED AT THIS.
THIS IS YOUR BABY?
THIS IS MY BABY.
RICK'S--
HOME OF SALMON GLUE.
A LITTLE SALT.
YOU WANT TO PUT SOME SALMON
WITH YOUR POTATOES?
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER
ONTO THE FLAT TOP.
ALL THAT CREAM SEEPS IN,
KEEPS IT MOIST.
WHILE THAT'S BROWNING,
WE'RE GONNA START THE SAUCE.
A LITTLE WINE,
SHALLOT, GARLIC.
YOU DIDN'T WANT
TO SAUTé
THAT GARLIC, THE SHALLOTS
AHEAD OF TIME?
NO.
NO? GOOD, VERY NICE.
A TOUCH OF TURMERIC,
JUST FOR SOME COLOR...
I LIKE IT.
SALT, LEMON JUICE.
WE'RE GONNA
REDUCE THAT BY HALF.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THAT.
CREAM.
GOING IN FOR OUR FLIP.
WOW, NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
SAUCE IS REDUCED. WE'RE
JUST GONNA ADD IN SOME BUTTER.
THE WHOLE COW.
TURMERIC.
WHAT AN IDEA. MMM!
SALMON, AND WE HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE GREEN ONION.
YEAH, SEE,
JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
MEDIUM-RARE RIGHT THERE.
MMM, WOW.
THAT IS THE PERFECT BALANCE.
SALMON'S PERFECTLY COOKED.
THE CRUNCH OF THE POTATO,
AND THEN SOME OF THE TEXTURE
OF THE POTATO
THAT WASN'T CRUNCHY.
THIS SAUCE IS SO LIGHT
BUT SO POWERFUL IN FLAVOR.
THAT'S...
DUDE, THAT'S
SLAMMIN' SALMON.
THE SALMON IS THE BEST.
PRETTY DYNAMITE.
AWESOME PIECE OF FISH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOVIN' IT.
ALL OVER THE BOARD
WITH FLAVOR, DON'T YOU THINK?
VERY MUCH.
ENJOY.
I LOVE EVERYTHING HERE,
QUITE FRANKLY.
TABLE NINE.
I ALWAYS WANTED IT
TO BE ABOUT THE FOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
A LOT OF DISHES
THAT WE SERVE HERE,
PEOPLE COME BACK
FOR THAT DISH.
AND KEEP COMING BACK.
BRANDY...
THEY KNOW YOUR NAME
WHEN YOU COME IN.
AND SUSAN.
THE PEOPLE THAT WE MEET, THEY
MAKE IT, AND THEY LOVE HIS FOOD.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
IT REALLY IS.
I'M HAVING THE PORK CHOP.
IT'S HUGE.
THE MEAT OF TWO CHOPS
BUT IN ONE. LOOK AT THAT.
MMM,
THAT'S A TOP CHOP.
SALMON B.L.T.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
KILLER SUN VALLEY CLUB.
THE POLICE CHIEF,
COUNCIL MEMBER,
THE MAYOR AND THE FIRE CHIEF
ALL HERE AT THE SAME TABLE.
I'M ACTUALLY HERE
BECAUSE THESE WINGS ARE SO HOT,
THEY MAY
SPONTANEOUSLY COMBUST,
AND THAT'S WHY WE NEED
THE FIRE CHIEF HERE.
ARE WE DEEP-FRYING THE WINGS?
GIVE ME THE RUN-DOWN.
NO.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE GONNA SEASON 'EM
WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
THEY'RE GONNA GO INTO
THE OVEN ABOUT 15 MINUTES,
GET 'EM A LITTLE BROWN.
WHILE THAT'S IN THE OVEN,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR SAUCE.
RICE WINE VINEGAR.
YES, IT'S NATURAL.
SAMBAL OELEK.
EXACTLY.
SOMETIMES YOU'LL SEE IT ALSO
CALLED A CHILI GARLIC PASTE.
SOME FRESH GARLIC.
CHOPPED UP.
I LIKE WHERE
THIS IS GOING ALREADY.
AND A LITTLE SUGAR.
WHITE WINE VINEGAR'S
A LOT SHARPER
THAN THE RICE WINE
VINEGAR.
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT A LOT
MORE OF THAT VINEGAR FLAVOR...
RIGHT.
THAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR,
THAT TANG.
TAKE JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF GREEN ONION.
WE LET THIS
SET OVERNIGHT.
SO REALLY TO MARRY
THOSE FLAVORS TOGETHER.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THEN WE GET INTO
MAKING THE CELERY SLAW.
CELERY SLAW--SOME BLUE CHEESE
CRUMBLES, SOME MINCED ONION.
THEN YOU TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPERCORN.
A LITTLE FRESHLY CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
WHEN I HAD LEARNED THIS
IN SCHOOL,
I JUST THOUGHT IT WAS,
BAM! I GOT 'EM!
THERE WAS NOTHING
LEFT OVER.
NOT A WHOLE LOT
OF PEPPERCORN.
NO.
YEAH.
A LITTLE SOUR CREAM,
JUST A LITTLE.
YEAH.
A LITTLE MAYONNAISE, A LITTLE
WORCESTERSHIRE, A LITTLE SALT
AND JUST A TOUCH
OF WHITE PEPPER--REAL BASIC.
USING GOOD BLUE CHEESE HELPS
TO GET GOOD FLAVOR FOR IT.
OH, THAT'S THE KEY.
TAKE SOME CELERY--
NOT TOO THICK, NOT TOO THIN.
THAT WAS IT?
WE ONLY DRESS IT
WHEN IT GOES OUT,
SO YOUR CELERY'S
STILL CRISP.
SO YOU GOT THE WINGS.
I'M GONNA TAKE OUR SAUCE.
WOW.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BUTTER.
SO LET THIS
REDUCE DOWN.
TILL IT CARAMELIZES.
OUTTA HERE.
GIVE IT NICE
LITTLE GRILL MARKS.
GET SOME
MORE CARAMELIZATION.
THAT SUGAR'S SNAPPING UP
ON THOSE REAL QUICK.
AND THEY'LL GO BACK
INTO THE PAN.
THAT'S A NICE TOUCH.
TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR BLUE CHEESE DRESSING.
THEN YOU TAKE THE DILL.
WOW.
AND WE'RE READY
TO PLATE.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU READY?
I'M READY.
MMM, WOW.
THAT IS NICE. THAT'S A GREAT--
BOY, THOSE ARE HOT.
MUCH BETTER WITH THE TONGS.
A LITTLE SPICE TO IT.
REALLY NICE.
GOOD BALANCE OF FLAVOR.
TONS OF POW WITH A COUPLE
OF THESE LITTLE CELERY NUGGETS.
YOU COULD TURN ME
VEGETARIAN WITH THAT.
NICE JOB. MMM.
YUMMY. THOSE ARE
DEFINITELY A FAVORITE.
THESE ARE SO GOOD.
LAYERS OF FLAVOR
IN THERE.
THEY'RE VERY DIFFERENT.
HERE YOU GO.
EVERYTHING YOU HAVE
IS GOOD.
ALL RIGHT. ENJOY.
WE LOVE COMING HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT'S JUST
AN AMAZING RESTAURANT.
YOU TELL ALL YOUR LOCALS
WHEN THAT LINE IS OUT THE DOOR,
IT AIN'T MY FAULT.
I'M JUST THE MESSENGER.
WE'LL REMEMBER THAT.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADING TO OKLAHOMA...
HERE YOU GO.
FOR A LOCAL TRADITION...
NO ONE ELSE
EVEN COMES CLOSE.
PILED HIGH.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE RUNNIN'
OFF THAT. YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
HERE ARE ARE, NORTHWEST AREA
OF OKLAHOMA CITY.
LOCALS AROUND HERE
CALL THIS "TEN PENN,"
TENTH AND PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE.
NOW IN JUST ABOUT EVERY
NEIGHBORHOOD, THERE'S THE GEM,
AND HERE AT TEN PENN,
THE GEM IS A RIGHTEOUS BURGER
AT A JOINT
CALLED NIC'S GRILL.
THERE'S ONE.
LOVE THE BURGERS.
IT'S GREAT.
BEST BURGER
I'VE EVER HAD.
HERE YOU GO.
A BURGER
THAT MAKES YOU HAPPY
THAT'S ALWAYS SERVED
WITH A SMILE RIGHT HERE.
NIC, THE OWNER...
THERE'S
YOUR BURGER, BUBBA.
HE'S JUST A GREAT GUY.
YOUR NAME'S NOT EVEN NIC.
JUSTIN NICHOLAS.
YES. THEY CALLED ME
NIC AS A KID.
MILO, YOURS FOR HERE?
NEVER DID
RESTAURANTS BEFORE.
NEVER.
TILL 12 YEARS AGO...
MUSTARD OR MAYONNAISE?
WHEN HE BOUGHT A HOUSE
THAT CAME WITH TWO APARTMENTS,
AND, OH, YEAH,
AND ABANDONED DINER.
YOU'RE A LANDLORD, A HOMEOWNER
AND A RESTAURATEUR
ALL WITHIN 50 FEET.
ABOUT LIKE THAT.
GOOD THING, TOO.
'CAUSE HE'S HERE ALL THE TIME.
I DO BREAKFAST
ALL BY MYSELF.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
YOU GET HERE AT 6:00 A.M.
TO DO BREAKFAST?
YEAH, I START BREAKFAST
ABOUT 7:00.
THE BEST BREAKFAST
IN TOWN--NO DOUBT.
HE'S GOT
EVERYTHING IN HERE.
LOOK, THERE'S
SOME LOVE RIGHT THERE.
THERE WE GO.
(Nic) JAVON
COMES IN AT 10:30...
ALL RIGHT.
THEN HE HELPS ME
THROUGH LUNCH,
'CAUSE IT TAKES
TWO OF US AT LUNCH.
OH, YEAH.
'CAUSE NIC'S
TURNED THIS 15-SEAT JOINT
INTO A LOCAL LEGEND...
REALLY WELL-KNOWN
THROUGHOUT THE CITY.
THERE YOU GO.
AND AT LUNCHTIME,
FOLKS PILE IN
FOR ANOTHER LOCAL LEGEND.
MMM, ONION BURGER.
THE ONION BURGERS--
THE BEST THING EVER.
THERE'S QUITE A FEW PLACES
IN OKLAHOMA THAT SERVES 'EM.
TWO BURGERS.
BUT NIC'S FAMOUS
FOR THE WAY HE DOES 'EM.
NO ONE ELSE
EVEN COMES CLOSE.
WHAT ARE WE DOING?
JUST PATTY-ING UP
SOME OF MY BURGERS.
IT'S ABOUT A HALF A POUND,
SOMEWHERE AROUND THERE.
75/25 BURGERS.
YOU GIVE THAT SIZE OF BURGER
FOR 5 BUCKS?
$4.25.
FOR 5 BUCKS.
I'M TELLIN' YA.
YOU JUST ROLL 'EM UP
AND PATTY IT.
I TRY NOT
TO PACK 'EM TOO TIGHT.
NO, 'CAUSE YOU PUSH ALL THE FAT
OUT OF THEM WHEN YOU COOK 'EM.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
AND THAT'S IT.
LET'S GO COOK THESE.
ALL RIGHT.
FIRST I USUALLY PUT SOME ONIONS
AND GET THEM SAUTéING.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
A LOT OF BUTTER.
GET 'EM GRILLIN' DOWN GOOD,
THEN PUT OUR BURGERS ON.
YOU THREW
THE BALL OF FUN ON THERE,
AND THEN JUST SMASH IT ON THERE?
I LIKE THAT YOU GET THE BUNS--
THEY'RE KINDA GETTIN' COOKED
ON THERE AND SOAKIN' UP
A LITTLE JUICE WHILE THEY DO.
THIS GRIDDLE'S
PRETTY HOT.
YEAH, THE HOTTER THE GRILL GETS,
THE GREASE GETS TO FLYING,
AND THAT WHAT MAKES THE--
GLAZES THE BUNS OVER,
AND PUTS A LITTLE EXTRA.
YOU SEE THE WAY HIS EYES
SPARKLE A LITTLE BIT
WHEN HE STARTS
TALKING ABOUT THAT?
HE SCARES ME.
THE ONIONS JUST SIT THERE
AND DO THEIR MAGIC.
IF YOU COOK 'EM TOO FAST,
THEY SKIN UP,
LOSE THE JUICE
AND ALL THAT.
A MESS OF ONIONS.
NOW WHAT CAN I GET
WITH THESE AS A SIDE?
FRENCH FRIES
OR MASHED POTATOES.
WELL, LET'S DO
SOME FRIES.
THAT'S JAVON'S DEPARTMENT,
ONE SPUD AT A TIME.
HE CUTS 'EM UP TO ORDER,
75, 100 POUNDS A DAY.
COOK 'EM ALL
IN PEANUT OIL.
YOU KNOW, IT TAKES A LITTLE
MORE HEAT, NOT BURNIN'.
PUT THE CHEESE
ON THE BURGER THE SAME TIME
THAT I DROP THE FRIES.
THEN YOU GIVE
THE CHEESE TIME TO MELT.
4 BUCKS.
$4.25.
I'M GONNA
TALK TO YOUR MOM.
HEY, I'M GONNA--
I'M GONNA TELL ON YOU.
YOU SEE IT STARTIN'
TO GLAZE UP.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET THIS
BABY OFF, BRING THE FRIES UP.
LET 'EM DRAIN OFF
A LITTLE BIT.
IS THAT
A NORMAL SET-UP?
THAT'S A NORMAL SET-UP.
DUDE, THAT'S HUGE.
LOOK AT THAT MONSTROSITY,
SERVED WITH MORE FRIES
THAN I'M GONNA BE ABLE TO EAT.
MMM,
THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE RUNNIN'
OFF THAT. YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
THAT'S WHAT
A BURGER'S SUPPOSED TO BE.
ONIONS ARE KILLER. MMM.
NO FRILLS, STRAIGHT-UP QUALITY.
I KNOW WHY
THIS PLACE IS PACKED.
IT ALMOST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
LIKE, IT'S SO FRESH.
JUICY, AND IT'S
A HANDFUL.
IT JUST RUNS ALL OVER
THE PLACE. IT'S GREAT.
THE ONLY BURGER JOINT
I'VE EVER SEEN
THAT GETS SERVED
WITH A FORK.
I EAT MINE
WITH MY HANDS.
I DON'T NEED A FORK
LIKE THE REST OF THEM USE.
OHH!
GETS A LITTLE SAUCY
HERE AT THE COUNTER.
EVERYBODY LOVES THE PLACE.
THANKS, BUDDY.
(Nic) SORTA SELF-TAUGHT.
WHATEVER I LIKE, THAT'S
HOW I DO MY RESTAURANT.
MAY SOUND CRAZY BUT, HEY,
RIGHT OR WRONG OR IN BETWEEN,
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
WELCOME TO NIC'S.
WHAT YA HAVING?
HE PASSES THE TEST
WITH ALL OF US.
EVERYTHING HERE IS GOOD.
I'VE HAD ALL THE SPECIALS.
THERE YOU GO.
AND YOU CAN SET
YOUR CALENDAR BY HIM.
TUESDAY SPECIAL...
NICE BIG
THICK PORK CHOP.
THERE YOU GO.
HERE'S YOUR MEATLOAF.
MEATLOAF ON FRIDAYS.
AND IT IS FANTASTIC.
MMM. THAT IS COMFORT FOOD 101
RIGHT THERE.
THERE'S
YOUR CHICKEN, BUBBA.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN'T BEAT
PAN-FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S ONLY ON THURSDAYS,
AND YOU BETTER GET HERE EARLY.
'CAUSE AT A CERTAIN TIME, NIC
DOESN'T TAKE ANY MORE ORDERS.
SO LET'S TALK
ABOUT FRIED CHICKEN.
WELL, FIRST, I'M GONNA MAKE
A SEASONING FOR MY CHICKEN.
I PUT MY SEASONING SALT.
AND WHERE'D YOU
LEARN THIS RECIPE?
MYSELF.
DO A LITTLE TONY'S CREOLE.
CAJUN SEASONING.
YES, SIR, AND THEN A LITTLE
BLACK PEPPER, A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC SALT AND THEN TOP
IT OFF WITH SOME ONION POWDER.
MIX IT UP,
SEASON UP THE CHICKEN.
SO NOW WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA MAKE?
I'M GONNA MAKE MY DREDGE.
WHAT DID WE JUST MAKE?
WE JUST MADE
THE SEASONING.
I SEASON THE CHICKEN BEFORE I
THROW IT IN THE SEASONED DREDGE.
HERE WE GO WITH THE FLOUR,
A LITTLE BIT OF CREOLE.
SOME SEASONING SALT,
BLACK PEPPER
AND A LITTLE TABLE SALT.
THEN I JUST MIX IT UP,
PUT ME A COUPLE IN THERE
AND THEN
I MIX 'EM AROUND.
SO YOU GET SOME SEASONING THAT
LAYS UNDERNEATH THE FLOUR,
SO IT REALLY COATS
TO THE CHICKEN.
ABSOLUTELY, YOU'LL
TASTE IT IN EVERY BITE.
OH, PLEASE. A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
SO WE TALK ABOUT PAN-FRIED.
SO WE GO WITH
A THIN AMOUNT OF OIL.
THE CHICKEN'S ACTUALLY GONNA SIT
ON THE BOTTOM OF THAT PAN.
JUST A LITTLE BIT. I THINK
IT GIVES A LITTLE THICKER CRUST.
BUT IT'S A DIFFERENT
KIND OF COOKING
VERSUS JUST SUBMERGING IT
AND DEEP FRYING.
THAT'S GONNA HAVE
A NICE CRUNCH TO IT.
TRY AND GET IT UP
TO ABOUT 165 DEGREES.
WHICH IS
THE COOKING TEMPERATURE
YOU'D LIKE TO SEE
YOUR CHICKEN AT.
ABSOLUTELY.
IF YOU COOK IT OVER, YOU LOSE
THE WHOLE JUICINESS OF IT.
THIS TAKES SOMEWHERE
AROUND 40 MINUTES.
LET IT GO FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES,
BUT THE TOP ON IT,
TENDERIZE IT WITH SOME STEAM
THEN TAKE IT OFF
AND BROWN IT
THE LAST 15 MINUTES.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT'S DELICIOUS.
LOOK AT HOW JUICY
THAT CHICKEN IS.
AND LOOK AT HOW CRISPY
THAT SKIN IS.
THAT'S MADE
IN SOMEBODY'S HOME
IN A 50-YEAR-OLD
CAST-IRON SKILLET.
YOU HEARD ME SAY IT
ENOUGH TIMES ON THIS SHOW,
BUT THIS REALLY IS--
YOU KNOW. SAY IT.
WINNER, WINNER,
CHICKEN DINNER.
YOU GOT IT. MMM.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL,
LOTS OF GREAT FLAVOR.
MMM.
CRISPY, IT'S VERY MOIST.
FRIED CHICKEN, BURGERS,
ALL THAT.
I'D SERVE ONE THING HERE--
BURGERS.
POTATOES
AND CHICKEN, TOO.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU ONLY GO BACK TO PLACES
THAT YOU REALLY LIKE THE FOOD.
(mumbling)
MMM.
IN DINER-ESE, HE SAID,
"THIS IS OFF THE HOOK."
THERE YOU GO, BUBBA.
IT'S THE BEST PLACE
TO COME IN TOWN.
(Guy) I SEE WHY EVERYBODY
LINES UP HERE.
TEN PENN'S
LUCKY TO HAVE YOU.
YOU SURE ARE THE GEM
OF THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
WELL, THANK YOU.
THANKS, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
COMING UP,
A TASTE OF TRINIDAD...
IT'S REALLY UNIQUE.
IN SEATTLE.
PELAU...
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE SITTIN'
AT HOME TO AN AUTHENTIC MEAL.
THAT'S A GOAT ROTI.
(bell dings)
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
MMM. YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D"
I THINK I'VE TRIED
JUST ABOUT EVERY TYPE
OF ETHNIC FOOD.
NOW I'M HERE IN SEATTLE
IN THE UNIVERSITY DISTRICT
ON A STREET THAT IS FILLED WITH
ALL TYPES OF ETHNIC RESTAURANTS.
NOW THE ONE THAT
HAS CAUGHT MY EYE, THOUGH,
IS THIS PLACE, PAM'S KITCHEN,
WHERE I HEAR THEY ARE
KNOCKIN' OUT THE REAL DEAL FOOD
FROM TRINIDAD.
...CURRIED CHICKEN.
I'VE HAD IT ALL.
I'VE HAD THE ROTI,
I'VE HAD GOAT, THE DUCK.
IT'S REALLY UNIQUE.
YOU READY FOR ROTI?
I LIKE IT. I'M HOOKED.
I JUST WANTED
TO BRING OUT EVERYTHING
THAT WE HAD BACK HOME.
THERE YOU ARE.
'CAUSE WHEN PAM JACOB MOVED
TO THE STATES 15 YEARS AGO...
CHANNA ROTI.
SHE HAD A PLAN.
I'M GONNA OPEN UP A RESTAURANT
SO PEOPLE CAN TASTE MY FOOD.
AND A FEW YEARS AGO,
SHE MADE IT HAPPEN.
ORDER TO-GO.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE SITTING
AT HOME TO AN AUTHENTIC MEAL.
FROM SCRATCH,
EVEN THE BREAD, A BUTTERY KIND
CALLED PARATHA...
I NEED ANOTHER PARATHA.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S FLAKY.
AND A STUFFED KIND
CALLED DHAL PURI.
I NEED THREE DAHL PURI
RIGHT NOW.
WE GONNA DO
THE DHAL PURI.
SO WE START BY USE
7 CUPS OF FLOUR.
UH, PAM,
THAT'S NOT A CUP.
SEVEN OF THIS,
BUT IT'S 4 CUPS.
7 CUPS
OF A 4-CUP MEASURING.
YEAH.
28 CUPS.
MM-HMM.
SALT, CRISCO,
BAKING POWDER, SUGAR,
AND HERE
WE START THIS GUY.
NOW WE POUR
THE WATER IN SLOWLY.
IT'S MAKING SOME NOISES I DON'T
THINK IT'S SUPPOSED TO MAKE.
I KNOW.
IT IS GOING
TO BLOW UP.
JUST USE A LITTLE OIL
TO HELP IT ALONG.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE THIS, JUST
SIT FOR, LIKE, TEN MINUTES.
OKAY.
OIL UP THE TABLE A LITTLE BIT
SO MY FLOUR DOES NOT STICK.
WHAT IS THIS,
A MASSAGE ROOM?
I JUST PULL
THE CORNER OF IT,
AND THE AVERAGE WEIGHT
SHOULD BE
BETWEEN 4 OUNCES AND 5.
THIS IS A LITTLE BIG.
THAT WAS YOURS.
THIS IS THE DAHL PURI FILLING--
YELLOW SPLIT PEAS, OIL
AND GROUND IT
IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
CILANTRO, HABANERO,
GARLIC.
NOW WE MIX
CUMIN, SALT.
OKAY, THEN I'LL TASTE
SOME OF THIS. THAT'S KILLER.
YEAH.
OH, WE'RE MAKING A SOPE.
♪ DRIVIN' THE BUS
TO FLAVOR TOWN ♪
A LITTLE FLOUR.
MM-HMM,
JUST ABOUT HOW MUCH SO...
HOW'S MINE?
GOOD. KEEP IT THERE,
AND YOU JUST FOLD IT LIKE THIS.
YEAH, GOOD, GOOD.
THIS IS GREAT STUFF.
PERFECT, SO NOW
YOU SQUEEZE THE MIDDLE,
SO THAT THE DAHL
JUST GOES ALL AROUND...
OKAY.
BUT YOU WANT
TO BE TENDER WITH IT.
AS SOON AS YOU'RE
DONE HOGGING THE ROLLER.
IF I CAN ACTUALLY TRAIN PEOPLE
TO WORK LIKE THAT,
I WOULDN'T BE
SO TIRED ALL THE TIME.
GIVE ME SOME.
SO NOW WE COOK THIS.
BIG AIR BUBBLE
IN THE MIDDLE, FOLKS.
YEAH.
COULD BE RISKY.
OOH, AND THEN A DOUBLE HAND-OFF,
WIGGLE-WAGGLE WITH IT.
THAT JUST LOOKS LIKE A BIG
OLD HUGE TRINIDAD TORTILLA.
SO THAT'S A DAHL PURI.
OKAY, GO TIME NOW.
GOOD, YES,
WE DO IT WHEN PEOPLE ORDER,
SO IT'S REALLY
NICE AND HOT.
PUT IT IN THE MIDDLE
AND YOU FOLD IT.
LIKE THAT.
YES. YOU'RE HIRED.
YOU'RE JUST HIRED.
OKAY.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE HEAT TO IT,
GREAT TEXTURE,
A LITTLE FLAVOR TO IT.
YEAH.
AWESOME.
COULDN'T HAVE THIS MEAL
WITHOUT THE BREAD.
IT'S PERFECT.
FOR SCOOPIN'...
YOU KINDA USE IT
AS A SECOND UTENSIL.
FOR SOPPIN'...
IT SOAKS UP ALL
THE SAUCES REALLY WELL.
AND FOR WRAPPIN'
ANY ONE OF THEIR SIX DIFFERENT
CURRIES CALLED ROTI.
LAMB ROTI.
CHICKEN ROTI.
BEEF ROTI.
SO THAT'S A GOAT ROTI.
(bell dings)
I LIKE THE GOAT
BECAUSE OF THE BONE.
THIS IS HOW
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE DONE,
MEAT RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE CURRY GOAT.
WE START WITH THE OIL.
OKAY.
AFTER IT'S HEAT UP,
I PUT A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN.
CUMIN.
THAT TELLS ME WHEN
THE OIL IS NICE AND HOT.
'CAUSE YOU CAN START
TO SMELL THE PERFUME.
YEAH.
SO WE HAVE JUST A TRADITIONAL
MADRAS CURRY POWDER.
FROM TRINIDAD.
A LITTLE BIT OF TURMERIC
FOR SOME COLOR.
YEAH, BUT FRIED
INTO THE OIL
BECAUSE IT BRINGS OUT
MORE OF THE FLAVOR.
I LIKE IT. ONIONS.
GARLIC. CAN NEVER HAVE
TOO MUCH GARLIC.
I AGREE WITH YOU ON THAT.
NOW GOES THE GOAT.
THIS IS A PART
OF THE LEG.
SO WE JUST CUT THE LEG UP INTO
ALL DIFFERENT KINDS OF PIECES.
YEAH, YEAH. CILANTRO.
CILANTRO'S BIG
IN TRINIDAD, TOO?
NO.
OKAY.
BUT WE DO HAVE SOMETHING
THAT IS SIMILAR TO IT
CALLED CHADON BENI.
OH, YEAH.
HAVE YOU HEARD
OF CHADON BENI?
NO, SHADOW BOXING, BUT NOT
PROBABLY ANYTHING LIKE IT.
HABANEROS, A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT ON THAT GOAT.
BLACK MASALA,
AND IT'S FROM TRINIDAD.
OKAY.
THIS IS ROASTED CUMIN.
SMELL IT.
(whistles)
SMELLS GREAT.
THAT IS GOOD, YEAH. A LITTLE
SALT, A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
OKAY, SO WE'LL
PUT A SEAR ON IT,
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN A PRESSURE COOKER.
RIGHT. I PRESSURE THE GOAT
BECAUSE IT'S TOUGH MEAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF LIQUID, 20
MINUTES IN THE PRESSURE COOKER.
WOW. OH, I'M DRIVIN'. YOU
DON'T HAVE TO GIVE ME IT ALL.
SO THIS IS THE GOAT.
MMM. OHH.
NICE CURRY, GARLIC AND ONIONS,
GOAT BALANCES OUT.
EXCELLENT DISH, EXCELLENT
TRY-IT-ONE-MORE-TIME DISH.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
KILLER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S VERY JUICY
AND TENDER.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THE FOOD
IN GENERAL IS IT'S HOMEMADE.
SOMETHING NEW. EVERY TIME, I
WANT TO TRY SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
PELAU...
I'M HAVING THE PELAU.
IT'S THE SPICES
THAT MAKE IT SO UNIQUE.
IT'S KINDA LIKE
TRINIDAD JAMBALAYA.
WITH A WHOLE LOT
MORE FLAVOR.
UH-HUH.
WHEN YOU COME BACK,
YOU'RE GONNA SEE
WHETHER OR NOT IT IS
BETTER THAN JAMBALAYA.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU.
YES, WE HAVING
A SHOWDOWN.
SO THERE'S A JERK CHICKEN
AND A CHANNA DAHL PURI.
AT PAM'S KITCHEN
IN SEATTLE, WASHINGTON...
GOAT AND CHANNA.
PAM JACOB IS COOKING
THE TRINIDADIAN FOOD
SHE GREW UP WITH...
THIS IS ACTUALLY
HOW WE DO THINGS BACK HOME.
FROM JERK CHICKEN...
THE SPICE IS WONDERFUL.
TO SCRATCH-MADE BREAD...
IT'S PERFECT.
AND PAM'S TAKE ON THIS
TRINIDADIAN FAVORITE.
PELAU...
CHICKEN, BEANS,
RICE, CARROTS.
IT'S KINDA LIKE
TRINIDAD JAMBALAYA.
OIL. WE'RE GONNA
BURN SOME SUGAR INTO THAT.
INTO THE OIL.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT'S GONNA
GIVE THE CHICKEN THE COLOR.
WHOA, WE'RE REALLY
BURNING IT
YEAH.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THIS IN MY LIFE.
SMELLS LIKE MARSHMALLOWS. YOU
KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING, RIGHT?
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
ALL RIGHT.
CHICKEN THIGH.
OH. CHUCKED OUR
BONELESS CHICKEN THIGH
INTO SOME OIL
WITH SOME BURNT SUGAR.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
TURNS LIKE TAR. THAT'S NUTS.
NEVER SEEN THAT BEFORE. AND IT
DOESN'T HAVE A BURNT TASTE?
NO.
SOME SALT. THE CHICKEN IS GONNA
START LETTING GO SOME WATER.
THE SALT'S
GONNA HELP FIGHT THAT.
YES.
BLACK PEPPER, GARLIC.
A LITTLE HABANERO,
OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THIS
IS A DISH FROM TRINIDAD.
YES, AND YOU ONLY USE--
THERE'S MIX-UP WITH ALL
THE RICES AND ALL THAT.
JAMBALAYA.
RIGHT, THIS IS
SIMILAR TO IT,
BUT WITH A WHOLE LOT
MORE FLAVOR.
BROWN RICE, KETCHUP.
AND YOU'RE SAYING THIS
HAS MORE FLAVOR THAN JAMBALAYA.
YEP.
WE'RE GONNA GET INTO IT.
OKAY.
ONIONS.
WATER.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
OH, YOU'RE VERY WELCOME.
BETTER THAN MY JAMBALAYA.
YOU BETTER BRING EVERYTHING
YOU GOT ON THIS ONE.
I TAKE IT BACK.
OH, NOT NOW!
OKAY, I USUALLY LEAVE IT
TO SIMMER A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY, WHAT KIND OF PEAS?
THIS IS PIGEON PEAS,
CARROTS, CELERY,
BELL PEPPERS...
SOY SAUCE.
SOY, A LITTLE BIT OF CILANTRO,
NOT TOO MUCH OF THIS,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
WHOA.
GREEN ONIONS, PUT SOME MORE
WATER IN AND COVER IT.
SO TRINIDAD JAMBALAYA,
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT.
AND HOW LONG YOU LET IT
SIT THERE UNCOVERED?
BETWEEN 35
AND 45 MINUTES.
TA-DA.
SMELLS GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW
IF THE BURNT SUGAR CHICKEN
CAN COMPETE
AGAINST ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK AT HOME?
WILL IT BE BETTER?
YOU HAVE NO FAITH.
MMM.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU WHAT,
THAT IS GREAT.
NOT JAMBALAYA GREAT,
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS?
IT'S COMPARING ORANGES
AND TANGERINES.
MM-HMM.
THE RICE IS NICE AND TENDER,
THE CHICKEN THIGH IS MOIST.
MMM, THAT'S DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD HERE
HAS BEEN DELICIOUS.
CRAZY, BUT DELICIOUS.
CRAZY. I LIKE THAT ONE.
(bell dings)
PELAU ON THE TABLE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
A LITTLE SPICY, FULL OF FLAVOR.
TELL ME IT'S NOT ROCKIN'.
OH, IT'S AMAZING.
SO UNIQUE.
AL PELAU...
THE FOOD
IS JUST VERY COMFORTING.
I LIKE IT.
I'M DEFINITELY A FAN.
YOU HAVE
DAHL PURI, TONY?
YEP.
YOU GOTTA COME HERE
TO PAM'S KITCHEN.
YOU'RE GREAT.
YOU ARE ONE GREAT COOK.
WOW, WAS THAT
A ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OH!
OH, OH!
TAKEN OUT ON THE POLENTA
AIR HOCKEY.