HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THEY LOVE GOING OUT TO EAT.
FAMILY STYLE IN
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND...
BACON OMELET?
YES.
WHERE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS...
GOOD.
ARE PUTTING THE TWIST
ON THE FAMILY COOKBOOK...
SPINACH PIE.
AND THAT MEANS HOMEMADE GRANOLA
IN THE PANCAKES...
SO MUCH FLAVOR IN IT.
AND RAVIOLI STUFFED
WITH BARBECUED CHICKEN.
HUGE PIECES OF CHICKEN
THAT ARE IN THERE.
MMM! OFF THE HOOK.
IN GLENDALE, CALIFORNIA...
YOU GOT THE CUBANS READY?
WHERE THIS FAMILY...
A LITTLE BIT OF CUBA
AWAY FROM CUBA.
IS CRANKING OUT
CUBAN CLASSICS...
FRIED STEAK, IT'S MY
FAVORITE DISH AS A CHILD.
FROM MOJO...
KIND OF LIKE
A CAROLINA BARBECUE SAUCE.
TAKE A WHIFF.
TO SHRIMP
IN AN EDIBLE CUP.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME.
YOU MADE SOME FOR YOURSELF.
AND IN HOUSTON...
I LOVE IT.
IT'S VERY DIFFERENT.
THIRD GENERATION COMFORT FOOD.
KIND OF A COMBINATION OF GREEK,
MEDITERRANEAN, MIDDLE EASTERN.
A COUPLE OF DUDES
BROUGHT OVER...
GOT SOME APPETIZERS READY.
FROM BOSNIA.
A CEVAPI SANDWICH.
MMM. I'M AN EXPLORER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
I SO DIG DOING TRIPLE "D"
ON THE EAST COAST.
ONE OF THE MAIN REASONS
IS ALL THE HISTORY.
HERE I AM,
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND,
AT A FAMILY-OWNED RESTAURANT
THAT'S BEEN OPEN
FOR MORE THAN 62 YEARS.
NOW A LOT OF BUSINESSES
HAVE COME AND GONE IN THIS AREA
BUT NOT THIS JOINT.
THEY'RE STILL SERVING GREAT FOOD
AT REASONABLE PRICES
TO COLLEGE STUDENTS,
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
LOUIS FAMILY RESTAURANT
IS ALL ABOUT.
(man) MEAT LOAF DINNER.
EVERYONE KNOWS ABOUT IT.
JUST KIND OF LIKE
A TRADITION.
(woman) YOU COME IN HERE,
IT'S LIKE FAMILY.
IT'S LIKE HAVING BREAKFAST
OR DINNER IN YOUR HOME.
(woman) NUMBER ONE...
IT'S CHEAP.
IT'S HUGE.
GOOD FOOD?
GREAT FOOD.
THANKS TO JOHN GIANFRANCESCO...
WESTERN WITH CHEESE UP.
AND HIS BROTHER ALBERT.
GOOD.
LOUIS IS LOUIS,
THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
(Guy) AND LOUIS
WAS YOUR DAD?
YEAH, HE WAS A COOK
IN THE ARMY.
AND WHEN HE GOT OUT,
HE OPENED THIS JOINT.
THANK YOU.
53 YEARS LATER,
THE BOYS TOOK OVER...
TURKEY DINNER UP.
SERVING SCRATCH-MADE
FAVORITES...
THE SAME AS THE FIRST TIME
I WALKED IN THE DOOR.
AND OLD STANDARDS
DONE JOHN'S WAY.
BARBECUED CHICKEN RAVIOLI.
JOHNNY ALWAYS GIVES US
SURPRISES. IT'S FUN.
I NEVER HAD
A BARBECUED CHICKEN RAVIOLI.
TODAY YOU WILL.
WE NEED TO MAKE
A BARBECUE SAUCE.
TOMATO SAUCE AND ONIONS.
HONEY, VINEGAR,
ORANGE JUICE.
GARLIC, THE PAPRIKA,
RED CHILI FLAKE.
CORIANDER, SAGE.
THE OREGANO.
PEPPER, SALT.
ROSEMARY, PARSLEY
AND THEN CARAMEL COLORING
THAT MAKES IT DARK BROWN.
THAT'S IT.
OOH, 16 ITEMS.
16 TICKETS TO FLAVOR TOWN.
ALL ABOARD!
I CAN'T BELIEVE I JUST SAID
THE "ALL ABOARD" PART.
OKAY, SO THE SAUCE IS DONE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON THE CHICKEN.
SO WE MAKE SURE THAT THE SAUCE
GETS ON THE FLESH.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
THEY'RE GONNA TASTE IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
TO THE OVEN WITH THIS?
YES.
HOW LONG?
TWO HOURS.
WHAT TEMPERATURE?
ABOUT 300.
MAYBE WE'LL RAISE IT UP LATER.
IF--IF WE'RE FEELING WILD.
THE CHICKEN READY?
YEP, LITTLE WARM.
LET IT COOL DOWN
AND THEN SHRED IT?
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT
IN LITTLE CHUNKS.
CHICKEN IN THE BOWL,
RICOTTA CHEESE.
FROZEN SPINACH.
PARSLEY,
PROSCIUTTO THAT WE MADE.
OH, A WHOLE BUNCH OF CHEDDAR
AND JACK, SOME PARMESAN.
IT'S EASIER IF I SAY IT
FOR YA.
YEAH. YEAH.
WHITE ONIONS
AND SOME MOZZARELLA.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT SIX EGGS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MIX
ALL THIS IN THERE, JOHNNY?
IT SEEMS LIKE...
TELL US WHAT WE'VE GOT,
JOHNNY.
THE BOWL IS A LITTLE SMALL.
YEAH.
WHOO.
WOW, THAT'S A GOOD-SIZE BOWL.
OKAY, SO THE EGGS GO IN.
YOU'RE GONNA WHISK THOSE UP.
WHISK WHICH.
OR JUST USE A SPOON.
WE CAN USE OUR HAND.
WE KIND OF HAVE
TO WORK IT A BIT.
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
FATHER HAD A CHEESE RAVIOLI
WITHOUT THE CHICKEN
AND THE PROSCIUTTO.
NOW WE GRAB THE DOUGH.
THAT WE MADE.
PUT FLOUR EVERYWHERE.
START IT OUT ON
THE HIGHEST NUMBER FIRST.
WE GOT TO DO IT A COUPLE TIMES
THE BIG WAY.
DIAL IT DOWN TO--WHOA,
YOU'RE GONNA GO THAT FAST.
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
I CAN PLAY THAT.
WOW.
NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
YOU WANT ME TO DO THE DOLLING
OUT OF THE...
YEAH.
OKAY, I JUST KNOW THAT
WE CAN'T HAVE IT ON THE EDGES.
LOOKING GOOD.
AND HOW MANY COME
WITH AN ORDER?
12, THAT'S ONE ORDER.
12, THAT'S ONE ORDER?
GET AFTER IT, ROCKY.
SO NOW THESE ARE DONE?
YES.
NOW THAT
IS A STUFFED RAVIOLI.
BOIL 'EM IN A LITTLE SALT WATER
TILL THEY FLOAT.
THERE WE GO.
THEY'RE READY.
THAT'S YOUR 12.
TOP 'EM WITH SOME MARINARA.
HEY, THAT'S ONLY TEN.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
I DON'T HAVE ANY LEFT OUT.
YOU ONLY GAVE ME TEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM! OH, MY GOSH.
LOOK AT THE HUGE PIECES
OF CHICKEN THAT ARE IN THERE.
THAT RIGHT THERE IS
AS GOOD AS ANY RAVIOLI
YOU WILL FIND.
OFF THE HOOK.
LOOK AT THE SPINACH, THE CHEESE,
STUFFED FULL.
THAT'S JUST AWESOME.
MADE THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
BARBECUED THE CHICKEN.
MADE THE MARINARA,
AND HANDMADE THE RAVIOLI.
MMM! UH-HUH, YEAH, COMMON,
EVERY DAY, SEE IT ALL THE TIME.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
TASTES LIKE HE KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOING.
SPINACH PIE, GOING OUT.
EVERYTHING'S MEANT TO PLEASE
THE CUSTOMER.
I LIKE GETTING
THE TURKEY DINNER AT 11:00.
OR IF YOU NEED LASAGNA
AT 5:00 IN THE MORNING.
(John) HASH UP.
CORNED BEEF HASH
FROM SCRATCH.
GRILLED PUMPKIN MUFFIN,
YOU JUST KNOW IT'S GOLDEN.
TOTALLY DELICIOUS.
TOTALLY.
BLUEBERRY PANCAKES.
PUMPKIN PANCAKES,
THERE'S JUST SO MANY OPTIONS.
I GOT THE GRANOLA PANCAKES.
YEP, WITH HOMEMADE GRANOLA.
THESE ARE SO GOOD.
GRANOLA PANCAKES, INTERESTING,
LIKE EVERYTHING HERE IS.
(John) SOME OLD-FASHIONED OATS,
SOME WHEAT GERM.
WOW, GETTING HEALTHY
ON THIS.
NOW SOME BRAN.
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT A NICE
STRUDEL-Y KIND OF THING
WHEN IT'S DONE.
STRUDEL-Y.
YEAH.
OKAY.
SESAME SEED.
I'M GONNA PUT THIS IN THE OVEN
FOR A HALF-HOUR AT 250, 300.
IT SMELLS TOASTY, DOESN'T IT?
IT DOES SMELL TOASTY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME FRUIT.
BLUEBERRIES AND CRANBERRIES.
YEAH. JUST ANOTHER TEN MINUTES
IN THE OVEN.
JUST FOR GRANOLA.
SMELLS GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME CINNAMON,
HONEY
AND SOME MAPLE SYRUP,
RAISINS, TOO.
WE'RE GONNA STIR IT
INTO THIS.
YES.
LITTLE MORE HONEY.
YEP.
YOU LIKE
MY DRIZZLING TECHNIQUE?
YES. THAT'S IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
LOUIS' PANCAKE BATTER
FROM HIS ARMY COOKBOOK.
EGGS AND SUGAR.
INSTEAD OF LARD
WE'RE GONNA USE CORN OIL.
MILK.
I DIDN'T BRING
MY GALLAGHER SHIELD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME SPICE.
NUTMEG, THAT'S HOW LITTLE,
ACTUALLY,
TURMERIC.
TURMERIC IN PANCAKE BATTER.
VANILLA WITH A LITTLE TOUCH
OF RUM IN IT.
VANILLA WITH RUM.
LOUIS LIKED RUM.
AND NOW OUR DRY INGREDIENTS.
FLOUR AND CAKE FLOUR
AND BAKING POWDER.
INSTEAD OF SIFTING,
WE'RE RUBBING.
HE'S RUBBING.
WE'RE WATCHING.
AND THIS GOES IN THERE.
WANT ME TO WHISK?
GO AHEAD. GO AHEAD.
DON'T LET ME GET AHEAD OF IT
OR ANYTHING.
JUST DUMP IT RIGHT IN.
OH, YEAH.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DUMP
THE GRANOLA RIGHT IN THIS?
YES, PROBABLY SLOWLY.
HOW ABOUT I DUMP IT ALL IN
AND THEN YOU TRY TO WHISK IT?
THAT'S IT. READY TO GO.
BUTTER DOWN THE GRILL.
HOW MANY PANCAKES
COME WITH AN ORDER?
THREE PANCAKES
WITH AN ORDER.
THAT'S A LOT OF PANCAKE.
AREN'T YOU HUNGRY?
(whistles)
I THINK THAT'S IT.
YOUR ORDER'S ALREADY READY.
I'M INTRIGUED WITH
THESE GRANOLA PANCAKES.
GOOD PANCAKE.
OH, GOOD.
IT'S GOT TEXTURE.
YOU GET SOME OF THE OAT
IN THERE.
YOU GET SOME OF THE FRESH FRUIT,
SOME OF THE RAISIN,
SOME OF THE HOT PANCAKE
ON YOUR FLIP-FLOP.
IT'S NOT SUPER SWEET.
IT'S A REALLY GOOD PANCAKE.
SO MOIST
AND SO MUCH FLAVOR IN IT.
CAN YOU EAT
ALL THOSE PANCAKES?
OH, YEAH.
BIG PORTIONS
OF REALLY DELICIOUS FOOD.
POACHED PASSION
FLORENTINE UP.
WHATEVER HE'S DOING BACK THERE,
HE'S GOT IT DOWN.
LOAF OF JOHNNY BREAD.
IT'S CHEAP,
AND IT'S SO GOOD.
ALBERT.
I LOVE YOU GUYS STICKING TO IT,
KEEPING THE BUSINESS OPEN,
HAVING IT AVAILABLE
TO THE COLLEGE STUDENTS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
WHAT A NEAT PLACE, MAN.
UP NEXT...
I LIKE FOOD WITH FLAVOR.
THAT'S WHAT COMING HERE IS.
WE'RE HEADING WEST...
ROASTED PORK.
NOT FRIED.
FOR A FAMILY DINNER
DONE CUBAN STYLE.
MMM.
I LIKE THAT A LOT.
SO HERE WE ARE ON THE SET
OF "TRIPLE 'D'--THE MOVIE."
ACTUALLY, NO, I'M JUST KIDDING.
THIS IS LOS ANGELES,
AND YOU'LL SEE THIS EVERYWHERE.
BUT WE ARE HERE
IN GLENDALE, CALIFORNIA,
WHERE A FEW MONTHS AGO
I WAS SITTING IN THAT
INTERSECTION RIGHT THERE
WHEN THESE FLAVORS
FROM THIS RESTAURANT
STARTED TO FLOW INTO THE CAR,
AND I SAID,
"WAIT A SECOND,
THAT'S CUBAN FOOD."
SO I PULLED AROUND
INTO THE PARKING LOT, RAN IN,
GRABBED A CUBAN SANDWICH
AND I SAID,
"MAMBO'S, OH, I GOT
TO BRING TRIPLE 'D' HERE."
YOU GOT THE CUBANS READY?
(woman) CUBAN SANDWICH.
BETTER THAN ANYTHING
I'VE HAD.
THE PORK IS EXCELLENT.
IT'S REALLY TENDER AND JUICY.
(speaking indistinctly)
(woman) FRIED STEAK, IT'S MY
FAVORITE DISH AS A CHILD.
I'M CUBAN.
THE KIDS LOVE IT.
THEY LOVE RICE AND BEANS.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU HAVE,
IT HAS A SPECIFIC CUBAN TASTE.
WE DONE THE REAL CUBAN FOOD.
PICADILLO...
THE KIND RAUL GONZALEZ
AND HIS FAMILY
WERE MAKING BACK IN CUBA.
MAMBO'S CHICKEN.
MY WIFE MIMA, SHE'S THE ONE
TO SHOW ME HOW TO COOK.
AND SHE'S THE ONE WHO HELPED
OPEN THIS JOINT 21 YEARS AGO.
HERE YOU GO.
WHAT ITEM ON THE MENU DO
YOU THINK YOU DO THE BEST?
THE PORK.
ROASTED PORK.
NOT FRIED.
AND THEY'RE DOING IT
THREE WAYS--
A BASIC SANDWICH.
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S JUST VERY NATURAL.
A TRADITIONAL CUBAN WITH HAM,
SWISS, MUSTARD AND PICKLES...
I LOVE THOSE TASTES TOGETHER.
OR A WHOLE DINNER.
ROASTED PORK WITH BLACK BEANS,
PLANTAINS AND RICE.
YEAH, I MEAN,
IT'S--IT'S PERFECT.
(whistles)
HOLY MOLY.
THAT IS HUGE!
LIKE 25 POUNDS.
DO WE SEASON IT?
NO.
NO SEASONING?
NONE.
WE JUST STICK IT
IN THE OVEN.
JUST THE WAY IT IS.
THE MEAT OF THE PORK IS SO RICH,
THEY DON'T NEED ANYTHING.
'CAUSE IT'S GOT ITS OWN FAT.
YOU GOT THE BONE.
THAT'S WHERE A LOT
OF THE FLAVOR COMES FROM.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, IN THE OVEN, 350,
FOR HOW LONG?
8 HOURS.
EIGHT HOURS. (whistles)
WHAT ARE WE GONNA WORK ON NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MOJO.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
A CAROLINA BARBECUE SAUCE,
REALLY THIN
BUT, BOY, DOES IT COMPLEMENT
THE SWEET BUTTERY FAT FLAVOR
OF THE PORK, OH.
FIRST, GARLIC, SALT.
LITTLE PEPPER.
LEMON, WINE.
(whistles)
THEN WE BLEND IT.
AND THAT'S IT.
YEP.
WHEN I WAS SITTING OUT THERE
AT THE TRAFFIC LIGHT,
THAT'S WHAT I SMELLED.
TAKE A WHIFF.
IS THE PORK READY?
YEAH.
WOW.
NOW THERE WAS NO LIQUID
IN THAT AT ALL.
LOOK HOW MUCH MOISTURE AND FAT
RENDERS DOWN.
NOW WE TAKE THE MEAT
OUT OF HERE.
NOW THIS COULD BE CRAFTED
INTO SOME TYPE OF A 1920s
FOOTBALL HELMET.
THAT'S THICK
AS MY HEAD!
SO NOW YOU SHRED
THIS UP.
WE'RE MAKING THE PLATE
OF ROAST PORK,
SO WE PUT A LITTLE CRISP
ON BOTH SIDES.
YES. ADD THE MOJO.
AND THAT JUST COOKS
ON TOP OF IT.
RIGHT,
WE TURN IT OVER.
A LITTLE MORE MOJO.
A LITTLE MORE.
NOW WE'VE GOTTA PUT
THE WHITE RICE, PLANTAINS,
THE MEAT AND THE BEANS.
AND THAT'S HOW IT COMES. I'LL
GRAB A LITTLE BIT OF THE PORK.
THAT LOOK LIKE
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING?
YEAH.
MMM.
I LOVE THE SECOND COOK
FROM THE PORK,
YOU KNOW, IT GETS THAT
LITTLE BIT OF CRUST.
YOU LIKE THE MOJO?
I LOVE THE MOJO.
IT REALLY BRINGS OUT THE FLAVOR,
AND IT COMPLEMENTS THE PORK.
A LITTLE BIT OF A SHARP BITE
FROM THE WINE AND THE GARLIC.
I JUST HAD
A MOJO MOMENT.
YOU FRESH-ROAST THE PORK HERE.
YOU MAKE THE BEANS YOURSELF.
YOU GOTTA LOVE THAT.
AND IF YOU WENT TO CUBA,
THIS IS HOW
YOU WOULD FIND IT?
(speaking indistinctly)
THE PORK WAS REALLY GOOD.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
AND IF YOU WANT IT SPICY,
YOU THROW YOUR OWN
HOT SAUCE ON IT, OTHERWISE,
YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
RIGHT.
BEANS FOR THE PORK.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE I COME
TO EAT THE RICE AND BEANS.
IF MY MOTHER SAW THIS,
SHE'D KILL ME,
BECAUSE I NEVER USED TO EAT
RICE AND BEANS AS A CHILD.
PLANTAINS THAT THEY INCLUDE
ARE AWESOME.
THIS IS VERY AUTHENTIC.
I COME HERE
BECAUSE IT'S LIKE COMING
TO MY GRANDMOTHER'S HOUSE.
IF GRANDMA'S LIVING
IN A CONVERTED GAS STATION.
THEY STILL HAD
THE FLOOR JACKS HERE,
AND THEY STILL
HAD THE OIL DRAINS.
UNTIL RAUL JR...
THERE WE GO.
HELPED HIS DAD
TURN THAT GAS STATION
INTO THIS.
WE WENT WITH THE BLACK
AND WHITE AND RED THEME.
AND WHO'S GOT
THE NOMAD?
RICHIE.
SICK.
TUESDAY NIGHTS YOU COME
DOWN HERE FOR CAR NIGHT,
EAT CUBAN FOOD,
LISTEN TO GREAT MUSIC--
THIS PLACE HAS GOT
TO BE GOING ON.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT OF CUBA
AWAY FROM CUBA.
ALL FROM FAMILY RECIPES.
COMBINATION OF FLAN AND CAKE
WITH STRAWBERRIES--VERY GOOD.
HERE WE GO, LADIES,
PAPAS RELLENAS.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A SHEPHERD'S PIE, BUT IN A BALL.
CRUNCHY, CREAMY
AND TASTY.
SOUNDS LIKE A SLOGAN.
AND THIS ONE...
TOSTONES RELLENOS.
THEIR OWN TAKE ON TWO
CUBAN CLASSICS...
MMM.
TWICE-FRIED PLANTAINS
CALLED TOSTONES,
AND FRESH SEAFOOD SEVICHE.
DOING IT WITH SHRIMP?
YEAH, WE CUT
THE SHRIMPS, GARLIC.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU'RE
GOING WITH THIS RIGHT NOW.
...IN LEMON.
IN LEMON.
ONIONS, TOMATOES, CILANTRO.
YOU GOTTA MIX THOSE TOGETHER.
MORE LEMON.
SO HOW LONG
DOES THAT MARINATE?
TWO HOURS.
THEN WE MAKE THE PLANTAIN.
WE'RE GONNA FRY IT
LIKE THIS.
JUST TAKE
A FEW MINUTES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
SMASH IT, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
HE SAYS HE'S GOT
SOME SPECIAL...
WHOA. WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
GONNA PUT A HOLE IN THIS THING?
YEAH.
SET IT HERE,
AND PUSH.
YOU MAKE TOSTONES CUPS?
YEAH.
I WANT A TOSTONES CUP MAKER.
OH, LET ME TRY.
ALL RIGHT.
PRESS IT DOWN.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS AWESOME!
SO THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS,
WE'RE GONNA FRY 'EM AGAIN.
ARE THEY READY?
YEAH.
LET'S PULL 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA FILL 'EM.
MOUTH'S STARTING TO...
YOU KNOW, RIGHT THERE,
IT STARTS TO WATER?
THIS IS A CULINARY
SHOT GLASS OF FUN.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME. I'M REALLY
SURPRISED ON THAT ONE.
MMM. CRUNCHY,
SOFT IN THE MIDDLE.
THEY HAVE A LITTLE
SWEETNESS TO THEM.
REALLY NICE TEXTURE
OF THE SHRIMP.
AND LOOK AT IT--
STILL HOLDING THE JUICE.
SHOULD HAVE MADE SOME
FOR YOURSELF.
THANK YOU.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
LIKE THAT. THAT WAS GREAT.
TWICE-FRIED PLANTAINS--I THOUGHT
IT WAS GONNA BE LIKE A CHIP,
OR A CORNMEAL-STYLE THING--
I LOVED IT.
THEIR PLANTAINS HERE
IS REALLY GOOD.
ENJOY.
I LIKE FOOD WITH FLAVOR.
THAT'S WHAT COMING HERE IS--
IT'S FLAVOR.
SO YOU GUYS WILL KEEP COMIN',
KEEP BRINGIN' PEOPLE?
ABSOLUTELY.
(man) ROPA VIEJA.
I EVEN BRING
MY CUBAN MOTHER.
RICE, BEANS,
A NICE PIECE OF STEAK.
I LOVE IT.
VERY PROUD OF YOU, MAN.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU.
CHEF, YOU DID A GREAT JOB,
I'M TELLING YOU.
NEXT STOP...
TWO CEVAPI UP.
TEXAS...
IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS,
AND THE OWNERS ARE GREAT.
WHERE THESE GUYS
ARE BRINGING BOSNIAN...
BOSNIAN HAMBURGER.
LOOK AT THAT.
TO BEEF COUNTRY.
WE TRY TO ADAPT
TO THE TEXAS SIZE.
THIS IS A BURGER
PLUS-PLUS.
ABOUT A HALF MILE OFF
BELTWAY 8
ON WESTHEIMER
IN HOUSTON, TEXAS,
IS A LITTLE JOINT THAT'S BEEN
OPEN FOR ABOUT TWO YEARS,
AND THEY'RE SERVING
A TYPE OF FOOD
THAT'S MAKING
ITS TRIPLE "D" DEBUT--
BOSNIAN.
WE'RE HERE AT CAFE PITA
TO CHECK IT OUT.
FIVE CEVAPI COMING UP.
VERY, VERY DELICIOUS.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S VERY DIFFERENT.
THERE'S A PLATE UP.
KIND OF A COMBINATION GREEK,
MEDITERRANEAN, MIDDLE EASTERN...
HUMMUS AND GYRO.
ALL OF THE ABOVE.
I'M HAVING SARMA,
WHICH IS STUFFED CABBAGE ROLLS.
SPINACH BUREK.
NEVER WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
I WOULD FIND
A BOSNIAN RESTAURANT
IN HOUSTON.
SPINACH BUREK READY.
THERE WASN'T ONE, UNTIL BOSNIAN
NATIVES OMER OKANOVIC...
CHICKEN KEBAB UP.
AND SLOBODAN MIJIC...
YOUR LAMB SHANK.
MOVED TO TOWN.
MY COUSIN--SHE'S THE ONE WHO
GOT ME TO COME INTO HOUSTON.
HE WAS LOOKING FOR A PARTNER,
AND I WAS LOOKING FOR A PARTNER.
YOU CAN GO AHEAD
AND TAKE 'EM.
SO A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO,
THEY OPENED THIS JOINT...
ALL RIGHT,
THANK YOU.
AND STARTED CRANKING OUT
HOMEMADE BOSNIAN CLASSICS.
FAVORITE ITEM
ON THE MENU?
OH, MY GOSH,
THE CEVAPI.
TWO CEVAPI
FOR TABLE ONE.
YEP, IT'S CALLED CEVAPI--
HANDMADE SAUSAGES
ON SCRATCH-MADE BOSNIAN BREAD.
HOW ABOUT THE BREAD, HUH?
OH, IT'S DIRTY.
I LOVE IT.
DIRTY MEANS GOOD
IN TEXAS, IN HOUSTON.
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT IS THIS BREAD CALLED?
LEPINJA BREAD.
LEPINJA. LOOKS LIKE A THICK PITA
OR A THIN CIABATTA.
INDEED, YES.
WHOA.
SOMETIMES WE JUST EAT THIS
WITH SOME CREAM CHEESE,
JUST FOR BREAKFAST.
MMM, THAT'S AWESOME.
THESE ARE THE WILD
NOOK AND CRANNY CAVES
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
I'M GONNA EXPLORE.
THEY MAKE IT ALL FROM SCRATCH.
MORE THAN 700 PIECES A DAY...
BREAD IS UP.
ON THE SIDE,
FOR THE SANDWICHES,
AND OF COURSE, THE CEVAPI.
BOSNIA, IT'S REALLY FAMOUS.
CEVAPI--OUR PRETTY MUCH
NATIONAL DISH.
THE GROUND MEAT.
80/20 GROUND BEEF?
YES. BREADCRUMBS,
BUT THEY ARE WET.
BRINGS IN SOME
MOISTURE, OKAY.
WE'VE GOTTA ADD SOME
PEPPER, SALT,
BAKING POWDER,
FRESH MINCED GARLIC.
A LOT OF GARLIC
IN BOSNIAN FOOD?
OH, A LOT, A LOT.
REALLY?
WE LOVE IT.
OKAY. GOOD,
I NEED ONE OF THOSE, TOO.
THAT'S NOT ACTUALLY FOR YOU.
THAT'S FOR THE MEAT.
SEE?
SODA WATER.
YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A LITTLE BIT OF...
A LITTLE BIT BREATHING,
A LITTLE BIT PUFF, UH-HUH.
A LITTLE BIT OF PUFF.
MM-HMM.
MIX IT NICELY.
WE'RE MAKING
PUFF THE MAGIC SAUSAGE.
ABSOLUTELY. JUST LET IT BLEND
FOR ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
RUN IT THROUGH THE MACHINE.
YOU KNOW, THEY MAKE
THESE ELECTRIC.
YES, I HAVE ONE,
NONE OF MY EMPLOYEES
LIKE TO USE THE ELECTRIC ONE.
EVERYBODY LIKES TO USE
THIS OLD ONE
THAT I ACTUALLY
BROUGHT FROM BOSNIA.
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR,
FIVE, SIX--
HANG ON, I GOTTA
TAKE MY SHOE OFF.
ALL OF THAT IS ON
ONE SANDWICH?
YES.
THESE ONES SET FOR A LITTLE BIT,
JUST IN THE REFRIGERATOR.
AND WE JUST
LAY THEM ON THE GRILL.
BETTER BE TEN.
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR--SEVEN,
EIGHT, NINE, TEN--PERFECT.
YOU PUT A LITTLE EDGE ON 'EM,
AND NOW YOU CAN MOVE 'EM.
YES.
YOU SEE WITH THE HEAT, THEY
START PUFFING UP A LITTLE BIT.
THAT'S ONE ORDER?
YES.
JUST GONNA GET SOME BREAD,
GONNA DIP THIS...
WHOA.
IN A BEEF BROTH
JUST LIKE THAT.
WHAT IS THAT?
BEEF BROTH.
I CAN'T EVEN SEE YOU.
ARE YOU THERE, AUNTIE EM.?
JUST WANT TO LAY IT OVER THAT.
NOW ALL THE STEAM AND JUICES--
THEY'RE GONNA
EVAPORATE INTO THE MEAT.
OH, THAT'S GETTING
NICE AND SOFT.
MM-HMM.
WE'VE GOT SOME ONIONS
ON THE PLATE
AND SOME KAJMAK,
WHICH IS CREAM CHEESE,
SOUR CREAM, FETA CHEESE,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
THERE WE GO.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
DIG IN. BEST THING...
OKAY.
IS TO DO THAT WITH HANDS.
TEAR IT OFF, GRAB SOME MEAT,
PUT SOME ONIONS ON IT,
DIP IT IN SOME KAJMAK.
MMM! THAT'S GREAT.
I MEAN, THAT REALLY IS GREAT.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
PRETTY ECLECTIC. A BREAKFAST
SAUSAGE TEXTURE,
BUT THEN I MOVE INTO
THE SWEETNESS OF THE ONION,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
TO THE MEAT,
AND THEN COMPLETELY
INTO A WHOLE NOTHER--
MMM--PITA-LIKE THING
WITH THE CREAM CHEESE MIXTURE.
THAT'S WILD. MMM.
CEVAPI. HURRY UP
AND TRY THE CEVAPI.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
ON THIS YUMMY BREAD WITH
THIS YUMMY CREAM SAUCE.
SAUSAGE
IS ALWAYS GOOD.
THAT'S A LOT OF WORK. COULDN'T
YOU JUST MAKE IT INTO A PATTY?
WE DO, IT'S CALLED
PLJESKAVICA.
VERY GOOD, PRETTY CLOSE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT'S LIKE AN INSIDE OUT
CHEESEBURGER.
WE PUT SOME ONIONS IN...
OKAY.
AND THEN WE PUT SOME
SHREDDED MOZZARELLA CHEESE,
SOME SAUTéED MUSHROOMS,
AND ADDED SOME SPICE TO IT.
CRUSHED PEPPER. THEN WE PUT
ANOTHER PATTY ON TOP,
AND THEN WE SEAL IT.
SO WE'RE HAVING
THE JUCY LUCY.
WE'RE HAVING
THERE YOU GO.
THE BOSNIAN HAMBURGER.
ON THAT SAME
BOSNIAN BREAD.
LOOK AT THAT. WOW.
HMM.
THAT'S GREAT, MAN,
AND A BIG BURGER.
WE TRY TO ADAPT
TO THE TEXAS SIZE.
THE CHEESE MELTS
REALLY NICE.
A LITTLE HINT OF THE MUSHROOM,
A LITTLE HINT OF THE CHILI.
THIS IS A BURGER PLUS-PLUS.
THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
IT'S REALLY,
REALLY YUMMY.
YEAH, I LIKE
THAT SPICY KICK.
BOSNIAN FOOD
IN TEXAS.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT REMINDS ME
OF BACK HOME.
(speaking indistinctly)
THE BOSNIANS THAT COME HERE--
THEY GET THE REAL THING.
SPINACH BUREK
COMING UP.
THIS IS A TRADITIONAL
BOSNIAN FOOD.
AND THEN WE TEACH THE LOCALS
THAT THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
I LIKE THE, UH,
THE UNIQUENESS OF IT.
GOT THE LAMB SHANK.
LIKE COOKING LAMB SHANKS
IN A CLAY POT...
FRESH BRAISED
LAMB SHANK...
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM, GOOD.
ALL RIGHT,
CEVAPI SANDWICH.
AT CAFE PITA
IN HOUSTON, TEXAS...
I GOT THE PLJESKAVICA.
BOSNIAN NATIVES OMER OKANOVIC
AND SLOBODAN MIJIC
HERE'S YOUR
SPINACH BUREK.
ARE CRANKIN' OUT
THE HOME COOKIN'
THEY GREW UP WITH.
REMINDS ME OF BACK HOME.
FANTASTIC. THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE LIKE IT.
GOT THE PLJESKAVICA
AND THE LAMB SHANK.
I'M HAVING
THE LAMB SHANK.
DONE THE TRADITIONAL WAY,
IN A CLAY POT.
LAMB SHANKS--
BIG IN BOSNIAN FOOD?
YES, IT IS.
LAMB--VERY, VERY POPULAR.
JUST WANT TO PUSH
THIS LEG FORWARD,
AND STUFF 'EM
WITH SOME GARLIC.
JUST SOME RAW GARLIC
THAT YOU KIND OF
SLIVERED A LITTLE BIT.
YES.
SO THE JUICE CAN START
POURING OUT OF IT.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SOME CANOLA OIL.
AN OLIVE OIL BLEND.
YES, SOME SALT, PEPPER,
OREGANO, ROSEMARY.
SO A PRETTY TRADITIONAL
RUB HERE.
YEAH.
SOME BAY LEAVES, BASIL.
SO MIX THAT ALL UP TOGETHER,
NOW HOW ARE WE GONNA COOK THIS?
JUST SEAR IT
A LITTLE BIT IN OIL.
SO THESE WOULD MARINATE
FOR 24 HOURS?
YES.
SO HOW LONG ARE THEY
GONNA GO--
JUST UNTIL THEY GET
A LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM?
YEAH, JUST GET
A LITTLE BIT
TO KEEP THE JUICES IN.
WE GOT ENOUGH
CRUST ON THERE.
OH, THIS SHOULD BE NICE.
WATER.
WATCH OUT.
SOME TOMATO SAUCE.
ADD SOME TOMATO SAUCE
TO IT.
AND SOME AJVAR...
MM-HMM.
LIKE A RED BELL PEPPER PASTE
MADE WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF EGGPLANT.
SO YOU LET THIS GO FOR
ANOTHER HOUR AND A HALF?
CORRECT.
POTATOES.
SO OVERALL, THIS IS GONNA GET
FOUR TO FIVE HOURS OF COOKING.
ABSOLUTELY, ABSOLUTELY.
A LOT OF LOVE.
(whistles)
ALL OF OUR DISHES TAKE TIME,
TO GET THE BEST
FLAVOR OUT OF IT.
I LIKE IT.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT. THAT BAD BOY
IS SIMMERIN' AND BOILIN'.
OKAY, SO...
JUST GONNA BRING OUR
CLAY POT, PUT SOME WATER IN.
IS THIS JUST TO DO IT
THE AUTHENTIC WAY?
WELL, OF COURSE, TRADITION,
BUT AS WELL THE FLAVOR.
GONNA THROW IN
SOME VEGETABLES...
EXCELLENT.
ZUCCHINI AND EGGPLANT,
ONIONS AND PEPPERS.
SO WE DON'T WANT TO PUT THE LAMB
SHANKS DIRECTLY ON THE BOTTOM.
WE PUT SOME VEGETABLES.
THAT'S WHY YOU PUT THE VEGGIES
THERE, SO IT DOESN'T BURN.
EXACTLY.
ADD THE JUICE TO IT,
FINISH OFF THE REST
OF THE VEGETABLES.
JUST ON A LOW SIMMER.
YEAH, VERY LOW HEAT,
LET IT SIT THERE...
THREE HOURS.
LET IT DO ITS MAGIC--YEAH.
BASMATI RICE.
OKAY.
NICE SHANK HERE.
FALLING OFF THE BONE.
LET'S PICK UP
SOME VEGETABLES.
AND THIS IS ALWAYS
ON THE MENU?
WE MAKE JUST SO MANY A DAY,
SO IF WE RUN OUT, WE RUN OUT.
WE RUN OUT, WE RUN OUT.
WE ONLY HAVE SO MANY CLAY POTS.
YEAH.
HE BROKE ONE RIGHT BEFORE
WE GOT HERE.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
MMM, EXCELLENT.
VERY MILD.
I PROBABLY GET MORE ACTUAL
LAMB FLAVOR THAN I EXPECTED.
BASMATI IS THE PERFECT
ACCOMPANIMENT.
FRESH-BRAISED LAMB SHANK--
THAT'S GOOD.
VERY GOOD.
IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
BUREK, COMBINATION
SPINACH AND CHEESE.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS ONE OF MY
FAVORITE RESTAURANTS.
I GOT THE GYRO COMING!
I KIND OF WORK MY WAY
DOWN THE MENU.
ANYBODY THAT WILL COME AND TRY
IT WILL MOST LIKELY ENJOY IT?
OH, YES.
IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS,
AND THE OWNERS ARE GREAT.
TWO CEVAPI UP.
GOOD FOOD IS GOOD FOOD,
WHEREVER YOU GO.
YOU GUYS GOTTA COME MEET
THE BAD BOYS OF BOSNIAN FOOD.
CAFE PITA. NICE JOB.
PLEASURE, GUYS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHOA! THAT WAS--
COUNTER WAS HOT.
(chuckles)
YEAH.
JUST CHECKIN'. DON'T PUT
ANYTHING THERE. WHEW.