I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
HEADED FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP, UPPER CRUST --
OUTRAGEOUS SANDWICHES
FROM COAST TO COAST.
IN PORTLAND, OREGON,
WHERE REUBENS ARE MADE
WITH PORK BELLYS.
THIS IS THE BEST REUBEN IN TOWN.
AND THIS FAVORITE'S GOT
SALT COD, POTATOES
AND CHORIZO.
MMM, FUNK-E-LICIOUS.
(Guy)
IN HOLLYWOOD, FLORIDA,
A TASTE OF PHILLY.
THE MEAT IS JUST EXCELLENT.
(Guy)
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN DOING
CHEESESTEAKS...
BIG FULL SANDWICH.
(Guy)
FOR MORE THAN 50 YEARS.
THAT WOULD ACTUALLY MAKE
SOME FOLKS NERVOUS IN PHILLY.
(Guy)
AND IN CHICAGO,
A DINER...
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
(Guy)
WHERE THE NAPKINS
JUST KEEP ON COMING
FOR POT ROAST, TURKEY...
(waiter)
OPEN-FACE TURKEY SANDWICH,
(Guy)
EVEN HOMEMADE DONUT HOLES.
TAKE TWO OF THESE
AND CALL YOU IN THE MORNING?
YES.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
JUST ACROSS THE MORRISON BRIDGE
ACROSS FROM DOWNTOWN PORTLAND
AND ACROSS THE STREET
FROM THE OREGON BALLET THEATER,
I GIVE YOU THESE SPECIFIC
DRIVING INSTRUCTIONS
BECAUSE I DROVE BY
THE JOINT TWICE,
IS THIS PLACE,
BUNK SANDWICHES,
WHERE TWO DUDES
ARE SCRATCH MAKING
THE NOT-SO-ORDINARY SANDWICHES.
HERE'S WHAT YOU GOT,
SALT COD WITH CHORIZO, AMAZING.
PORK BELLY REUBEN,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
CURED MEAT...
THE ITALIAN CURED MEAT
WITH PICCANTE PEPPERS, AWESOME.
(waitress)
ALL RIGHT, I HAVE A MEATBALL
AND A PO' BOY.
ECLECTIC AND FUNKY,
BUT GOOD QUALITY FOOD.
THIS IS LIKE REAL FOOD.
YEAH.
(Guy)
MADE BY A COUPLE OF
REAL FOOD FANATICS...
ALL RIGHT,
I'VE GOT A CURED MEAT.
(Guy)
TOMMY HABETZ
AND NICK WOOD
WHO MET AT A FINE DINING JOINT.
I HIRED NICK,
HE WAS MY SOUS CHEF.
WE ALWAYS REALLY ENJOY
MAKING SANDWICHES,
SO WE DECIDED TO OPEN
A SANDWICH SHOP.
THERE'S ALWAYS
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
(Guy)
LIKE BUNK'S OWN
HOUSE CURED PORK BELLY.
YOU CAN PUT PORK BELLY
ON ANYTHING AND YOU'RE
GONNA BE ALL RIGHT.
(Guy)
FROM A PO' BOY...
OH, MY GOD,
IT'S SO GOOD.
(Guy)
TO A VIETNAMESE BANH-MI,
EVEN THEIR REUBEN.
I'M DYING TO TRY
THE PORK BELLY REUBEN.
THIS IS THE BEST REUBEN IN TOWN.
NOT SOMETHING YOU SEE
ON EVERY SANDWICH MENU,
BUT I'M DOWN WITH IT.
THE CURE IS GONNA BE
THESE DRY INGREDIENTS.
WE'LL START OFF
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF CHILI FLAKE,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
FENNEL SEED,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA BUZZ THAT.
I THINK THIS IS ONE OF
THE BIGGEST MISTAKES
PEOPLE MAKE
IS NOT USING
REALLY FRESH SPICES.
THROW A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR
IN THERE.
THIS IS LIKE 50/50,
SALT AND SUGAR.
YOU MEANT FITTY/FITTY.
FITTY/FITTY,
YEAH, TOUCHE.
A LITTLE BIT
ON THE BOTTOM FIRST.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA PACK
THAT BAD BOY RIGHT DOWN INTO IT.
A LITTLE BIT ON TOP OF THERE,
RUB IT DOWN REAL GOOD,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
AND WE'LL PUT
SOME OF THIS THYME ON THERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GRATE
A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG.
A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG,
A LITTLE MORE PATTY, PATTY.
JUST RUB IT IN
AND IT'S GONNA SIT
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ROAST IT OFF,
SLOW COOK IT.
YEAH, FOR LIKE FOUR HOURS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA BEGIN
THE RUSSIAN DRESSING.
IT'S PRETTY SIMPLE,
JUST MAYONNAISE,
KETCHUP, POMMERY MUSTARD,
A LITTLE EGG IN THERE,
CHOPPED PICKLES.
THAT'S A GREAT LOOKING DRESSING.
JUST A LITTLE SALT
AND BLACK PEPPER,
RED WINE VINEGAR,
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
THE LAST THING I DO
FOR MY RUSSIAN DRESSING
IS I JUST STIR IN
A LITTLE BIT OF BACON FAT.
A LITTLE BIT!
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
MAYBE I SHOULD TRY
THIS DELICIOUS-NESS.
MMM, WOW, OH DUDE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW IF IT'S FAIR
TO CALL THAT RUSSIAN DRESSING.
I MEAN, YOU GOTTA CALL THAT
LIQUID MOSCOW OR SOMETHING.
SO WE HAVE OUR CURED
PORK BELLY.
NOW COOL IT DOWN, SLICE IT,
AND MAKE A SANDWICH.
TOTALLY.
I'LL PUT IT BACK,
I'LL WAIT FOR THE SANDWICH.
WE TAKE SOME DARK RYE,
BRUSH SOME DRESSING ON THAT.
A LITTLE SWISS,
THEN OUR PORK BELLY.
A LITTLE FRESH
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
OUR SAUERKRAUT.
BRUSH THIS DOWN
WITH SOME BUTTER.
TALK ABOUT THE MEANY PANINI.
TOSS THIS ON THERE.
AND YOU PUT THE SLAMA
ON THE CLAMA?
THAT COOKS FOR
JUST A FEW MINUTES
TO CRISP UP A LITTLE BIT
AND FINISH IT OFF
IN THE OVEN.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
YOU'VE GOT
THE SUBTLENESS OF THE PORK,
MIXED WITH THE REALLY NICE RUB
YOU PUT ON IT,
YOU SLOW COOKED IT,
RENDERED DOWN THE FAT.
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT, MAN.
I DON'T THINK I'VE ACTUALLY HAD
A BETTER SANDWICH.
IT'S SO GOOD.
IT'S A NICE TWIST
ON THE TRADITIONAL SANDWICH.
I NEED A CURED MEAT SANDWICH.
TALK ABOUT DIVERSIFIED.
I KNOW.
WE'RE TRYING TO DO STUFF
THAT WE REALLY LOVE
LIKE TRIPE, TONGUE, SALT COD.
SALT COD AND CHORIZO
WITH MARINATED OLIVES,
IT'S AMAZING.
(Guy)
WAIT A SECOND.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE SALT COD
AND YOU'RE GONNA MAKE ME
A SANDWICH OUT OF IT.
I SURE AM.
THESE ARE TOTALLY FLAVORS
LIKE, FROM SPAIN.
THIS IS THE OLD SCHOOL WAY.
WHY DO THEY SALT COD,
PRESERVATION?
PRESERVATION, YEAH,
SO WE'VE GOT
THIS BEAUTIFUL SALT COD,
I'M JUST GONNA
THROW IT IN HERE.
WE'VE GOTTA SOAK THIS
BECAUSE WE'VE GOT TO
PULL SOME OF THAT SALT OUT
AND RE-HYDRATE IT.
THEN I'M GONNA
COVER IT IN WATER.
LET IT SOAK FOR A DAY OR TWO?
A COUPLE DAYS, AND WE CHANGE
THE WATER A FEW TIMES.
THIS IS THE COD
THAT'S BEEN SOAKING
WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE IT...
SO YOU'D GIVE THAT COD THE NOD?
I'M GIVING IT THE NOD.
THROW IN JUST A HANDFUL OF
GARLIC CLOVES.
WE'VE GOT SOME THYME
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
COVER THIS WITH MILK.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS ANTICIPATING.
WE'LL COOK IT REALLY SLOWLY
UNTIL IT FLAKES APART.
THEN WE'LL STRAIN IT
OUT OF THE MILK.
THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A PUREE OUT OF IT.
OUT OF THE FISH.
OUT OF THE FISH
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF
MASHED POTATO.
JUST WHAT I THOUGHT
I WOULD BE GETTING
WHEN I PULLED INTO
THIS LOCAL SANDWICH SHOP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT OF
CRUSHED GARLIC TO THIS.
THYME JUST TO BUMP IT UP
IN THE FRONT.
WHAT HE MEANS
BY BUMPING IT UP TO THE FRONT,
IT'S GOT THE DEPTH OF THE THYME
ALL THROUGH THE DISH,
YOU PUT THAT THYME IN FRESH
LIKE THAT
YOU'LL REALLY GET
A LITTLE FORWARD TASTE OF IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM,
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUREE THIS UP.
HE'S FLINGIN' FISH.
OH, IT'S CHUNKY.
YEAH, IT'S GONNA
BE CHUNKY, FOR SURE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
AND I THINK WE'RE GOOD
TO BUILD A SANDWICH.
WE'VE GOT THESE BEAUTIFUL ROLLS
FROM A LOCAL BAKERY.
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL
AND I'M GONNA THROW IT
ON THE PRESS
JUST TO GET
A LITTLE HEAD START.
TAKE THE BREAD OFF THE GRILL
AND SPREAD THE SALT COD PUREE.
THROW IT IN THE OVEN,
BROWN IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
WHILE THAT'S GOING
WE'RE GONNA MAKE UP THE SALAD.
PARSLEY, A LITTLE
THINLY SLICED RED ONION,
OIL-CURED BLACK OLIVES,
SPANISH CHORIZO
THAT'S BEEN SLICED AND FRIED UP.
THEN WE ADD A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
RED WINE VINEGAR.
HERE'S THE SALAD OF FIERI.
TAKE THIS AND PUT IT
RIGHT ON THE SANDWICH,
CUT IT UP,
AND SERVE IT.
MMM, TALK ABOUT EATING SOMETHING
THAT JUST CONTINUES TO OPEN UP.
OH, THAT'S NICE, THAT'S CRAZY.
THE TEXTURE AND THE FLAVOR --
THE CREAMINESS OF THE POTATOES,
THE SHARPNESS OF THE VINEGAR,
ALL OF A SUDDEN
CHORIZO STORMS THROUGH THE DOOR.
I MEAN, THERE'S SO MANY
COMPONENTS TO IT.
IF YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A GOURMET SANDWICH,
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF I WANT TO CALL IT GOURMET,
I WANT TO CALL IT
FUNK-E-LICIOUS.
GET THE FUNK AT BUNK.
IT'S LIKE A SALTY SALAD
IN A SANDWICH.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
FRESH INGREDIENTS,
GOOD INGREDIENTS,
THEY DO EVERYTHING WELL.
IT'S THE ONE THING
THAT PORTLAND NEEDED.
WAS A RIGHTEOUS
HANDMADE SANDWICH JOINT.
A RIGHTEOUS
WHEN I COME BACK TO PORTLAND,
I'M COMING TO BUNK.
LOAD THE TRUNK
WHEN YOU GO TO THE BUNK.
I GOTTA MAKE UP
ALL MY BUNK WORDS
AND SEND 'EM TO YOU.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
IT'S FABULOUS,
I LOVE THE CHEESE.
WE'RE HEADING EAST
FOR A PHILLY FAVORITE
IN FLORIDA.
MMM, THE THIN SLICE ON THE MEAT
AND THE ONIONS
ON A FRESHLY BAKED ROLL.
MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS OF
"D.D.D.," DO I HAVE
A DOOZY FOR YOU.
I'M IN HOLLYWOOD,
NOT CALIFORNIA,
BUT FLORIDA,
WHERE I AM GETTING READY
TO ENJOY A PHILLY CHEESESTEAK
AND NOT SEAFOOD
AT A PLACE CALLED SONNY'S
THAT'S OWNED BY A GUY
NAMED JOHN
AT A BUILDING THAT LOOKS NEW,
BUT IS ACTUALLY 50 YEARS OLD.
OH, I KNOW,
THIS MAKES COMPLETE SENSE.
WE GOTTA CHECK OUT
SONNY'S FAMOUS STEAK HOGIES.
STEAK, ONION, AND CHEESE.
BIG FULL SANDWICH.
ONION, SAUSAGE, CHEESE.
WE CALL THAT THE HUNCH
ON "D.D.D."
(Guy)
THEY'VE BEEN HUNCHING HERE
FOR HALF A CENTURY.
AND 1958 IS WHEN
MY DAD OPENED HERE.
(Guy)
DAD WAS SONNY.
NOW JOHN'S RUNNING THE SHOW.
YOU INHALE THE SANDWICH
WHEN YOU GET IT,
VERY GOOD.
(Guy)
FROM THE CLASSIC CHEESESTEAK...
IT'S FABULOUS,
I LOVE CHEESE.
(Guy)
TO THE ITALIAN HOGIE...
THE MEAT IS JUST EXCELLENT.
(Guy)
AND A MEATBALL SUB...
THEY'RE TASTY,
THEY'RE SOFT.
(Guy)
WITH HOMEMADE SAUCE ON,
GET THIS, HOMEMADE BREAD.
WE MAKE OUR BREAD EVERY DAY.
IT'S ALL IN THE BREAD.
HOW MANY ROLLS
DO YOU MAKE A DAY?
BETWEEN 30 AND 50 DOZEN.
BETWEEN 30 AND 50 DOZEN, OKAY.
WE START WITH THE WATER.
THIS IS FRESH YEAST,
HEAT IT UP WITH SOME WATER.
THEN I HAVE SALT,
I HAVE DIAMALT.
WHO?
DIAMALT IS
THE FOOD FOR THE YEAST.
FLOUR, 11 1/2 POUNDS
TO START WITH.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE
AND THEN WE'LL ADD
SOME BUTTER AND SHORTENING.
ANOTHER 12 POUNDS OF FLOUR.
THIS IS NOT
YOUR FIRST RODEO
IS IT THERE, JOHNNY?
NO.
WHEN THE DOUGH STARTS
BEING CARRIED BY THE HOOK
IT'S READY TO GO.
NOW WE TAKE IT OUT
AND WHERE DOES IT GO?
IT GOES INTO A DOUGH BOX
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
THEN WE PUNCH IT DOWN
AND IT STARTS TO COME UP AGAIN.
THIS IS ONE THAT WE'VE PUNCHED,
FOLD, FOLD, FOLD, AND PUT
IT BACK.
RIGHT.
OH, YOU SHOULD
FEEL HOW WARM IT IS.
WHAT SIZE ARE WE GOING FOR?
4 1/2 OUNCES.
THAT IS DEAD-ON.
I WOULD SAY THAT'S PERFECT.
THANK YOU, I'M OUT.
THAT WAS PERFECT.
PUT 'EM ON OUR METAL PAN
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
IN THE METAL PROOF BOX.
IT'S GONNA GET
ANOTHER TEN MINUTES
AND THEN WE'LL ROLL 'EM OUT.
WE'LL PRESS 'EM DOWN
WITH OUR FINGER,
WE WANT TO FOLD IT UP,
TURN IT OVER, ROLL IT OUT,
THEN I PUT THESE
IN THE METAL PROOF BOX.
AND THEY GO ROUND THREE.
NEXT THING WE'LL DO
IS SCORE 'EM, BUTTER 'EM,
AND POP 'EM IN THE OVEN.
PUSH IT ALL THE WAY DOWN
TO THE BOTTOM AND THEN
IT WILL STOP.
'ROUND AND 'ROUND IT GOES.
OH, THESE MUST BE
THE ONES I ROLLED.
INTERESTING HOW IT GETS
A LITTLE CRACKLE TO IT.
MMM, GREAT CRUST, BUT LIGHT,
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
IT MAKES THE WHOLE SANDWICH.
(Guy)
LIKE THE ONE FOLKS HAVE BEEN
LINING UP FOR SINCE 1958.
CHEESESTEAK,
THIS IS THE SECOND.
IT DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER.
WHAT WE HAVE HERE
IS BONELESS RIBEYE.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BIT FROZEN,
JUST POP IT IN THE SLEEVE.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR LIKE,
1/16th OF AN INCH.
YOU'VE GOT THAT SO THIN
THERE'S ONLY ONE SIDE TO IT.
GOES ON THE LINE,
YELLOW ONIONS.
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE BIT OF
BUTTER ON THE SIDE.
ALWAYS BETTER WITH BUTTER,
AND THEN COVER IT.
WE'RE JUST WAITING FOR IT
TO GET TO A POINT WHERE
WE CAN BREAK IT UP,
PUT A LITTLE SAUCE ON TOP,
A LITTLE BUTTER AGAIN,
MIX IT ALL TOGETHER,
AND NOW I'M READY TO PUT
MY PROVOLONE CHEESE ON.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
MMM, MMM.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
A LITTLE BIT OF MELTED CHEESE,
THE THIN SLICE ON THAT MEAT,
THE ONIONS,
ON A FRESHLY BAKED ROLL.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE KICKER
ON THAT IS, THE BUTTER.
THE BUTTER'S WHAT DOES THAT.
IT WOULD ACTUALLY MAKE
SOME FOLKS NERVOUS IN PHILLY.
(customer)
THIS IS WHAT
I COME HERE FOR.
THIS IS THE BEST STEAK SANDWICH
IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
(Guy)
IF YOU CAN FIGURE OUT
HOW TO ORDER ONE.
THIS IS A 95.
FOUR KINDS OF STEAK HOGIES,
50, 95, 90, AND 9.
"5" IS LIKE AN "S" FOR SAUCE,
"0" IS "O" FOR ONIONS,
THE 9, YOU TURN IT AROUND
AND IT'S A "P," PLAIN.
A 50 IS "S-O,"
SAUCE AND ONIONS,
A 95 IS PLAIN WITH SAUCE,
AND A NUMBER 9
IS TOTALLY PLAIN.
SO YOU HAVE THE 50?
THE 90.
WHAT NUMBER IS THAT?
90, PLAIN WITH ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT OF
SAUCE ON THERE, PERFECT.
THE SAUCE IS GREAT.
(Guy)
FROM AN OLD FAMILY RECIPE
LOADED WITH VEGGIES...
WE'RE GONNA PUREE ALL OF THIS
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
THROUGH THAT STRAINER
AND IT WILL PUSH
EVERYTHING DOWN.
I GOTTA TRY THIS.
MMM, GREAT,
CAN'T DOUBLE DIP,
I GOTTA GET SOME BREAD.
ANYTHING YOU PUT THAT SAUCE ON
IS GOOD.
(Guy)
FROM THE CHICKEN PARM
TO THE PASTA...
WE COME LIKE
EVERY WEEK TO HAVE IT.
(Guy)
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE
SECOND ONLY TO
THE CHEESESTEAK.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'VE GOT FOUR POUNDS OF
BREADCRUMBS.
WE GRIND OUR OWN BREADCRUMBS
FROM OUR BREAD.
PECORINO/ROMANO GRATED CHEESE.
THIS IS A GARLIC POWDER
AND BLACK PEPPER.
FRESH GARLIC,
FRESH PARSLEY.
RED BELLS, ONIONS, CELERY,
THEN WE MIX IT.
GET THAT ALL INCORPORATED
AND THEN ADD WATER.
YEAH, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR EGGS
AND LET THAT MIX AROUND
AND THEN WE'RE READY FOR
THE MEAT.
WHEN YOU PUT THE MEAT IN
YOU WANT AS LITTLE TIME
AS POSSIBLE.
RIGHT.
THIS IS ACTUALLY
A LITTLE BIT LEANER
THAN THE 80/20.
SO 85/15?
YES.
WHEN IT'S ALL MIXED TOGETHER
WE MAKE 'EM INTO
LITTLE FOOTBALLS.
SO THEY FIT CYLINDERALLY...
SO THEY FIT ON THE ROLL.
SCOOPING 'EM OUT.
SET, SCOOP,
OFF THE PALM OF THE HAND, DOWN.
WE'RE A GOOD TEAM, JOHNNY.
I'M GONNA COME AND PLAY
AT YOUR HOUSE MORE OFTEN.
THEY GO IN THE OVEN,
400 DEGREES FOR AN HOUR.
AT 400?
THEY COME OFF
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR
ON THE TOP OF IT
AND IT'S STILL VERY TENDER.
THAT'S NUTS,
ACTUALLY THOSE ARE MEATBALLS.
TAKE A ROLL,
TAKE A COUPLE OF MEATBALLS
AND GO IN AT AN ANGLE
AND PUT SOME SAUCE ON.
THE MEATBALL IS AS TENDER
AS YOU CAN FIND.
GREAT TOMATO SAUCE,
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
THERE'S NO PLACE BETTER.
IT'S JUST ONE OF THE THINGS
YOU GOTTA HAVE.
TWO 90s WITH PROVOLONE.
A 50 WITH CHEESE.
FOR 40 YEARS
THIS HAS BEEN
THE MEAL FOR US.
ONCE YOU'RE HERE,
YOU CAN'T WAIT
TO GET BACK.
CARE ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE DOING
AND DO IT THE RIGHT WAY.
YOU RUN A REALLY NICE OPERATION,
YOU HAVE A GREAT PEOPLE,
FANTASTIC FOOD.
CONGRATULATIONS,
IT'S VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU.
(Guy)
NEXT STOP, CHICAGO...
SOMETHING THAT YOUR MOM MADE,
BUT BETTER.
(Guy)
FOR JUST A LITTLE SOMETHING.
OOH, IT'S HOT,
TENDER, GREAT ROLL.
THE GRAVY'S CRAZY, WHAT?
HEY, COME HERE, CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS ONE OF
THE SMALLEST NEIGHBORHOODS
ON THE WEST SIDE OF CHICAGO.
THIS IS WHERE CAPONE
AND HIS BOYS USED TO RUN.
THIS PLACE RIGHT HERE
IS THE DEPOT WHERE YOU GET
THE TROLLEYS AND THE BUSES.
BACK IN THE DAY
YOU COULD GET A RIDE,
PICK UP A SANDWICH,
OR LAY DOWN A BET,
IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
ME TODAY, I'M HERE TO SEE
A GUY ABOUT A THING AT
THIS PLACE.
THEY GOT THE STUFF,
YOU UNDERSTAND, ALL RIGHT.
NO, I'M JUST KIDDING.
THIS IS THE DEPOT DINER
WHERE YOU HAVE GOTTA COME
AND SEE THIS FIVE-STAR CHEF
AND WHAT HE'S DOING
TO DINER FOOD, OFF THE HOOK.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
EXPLAIN THIS TO ME.
THIS IS THE APPLE PANCAKE
AND IT'S GOT LEGITIMATE
APPLE IN IT.
HOW MANY OF THESE DO YOU ROAST?
ONE A DAY, SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
THE WHOLE TURKEY'S IN THERE
AND HALF A PIG.
HERE'S YOUR OPEN-FACED
TURKEY SANDWICH.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S SOMETHING
YOUR MOM WOULD MAKE, BUT BETTER.
(Guy)
'CAUSE IT'S ALL MADE
BY TRAINED CHEF ROBERT NAVA
WHO WENT LOOKING FOR
A WHITE TABLECLOTH JOINT
AND FOUND THIS INSTEAD.
I LIKE THE HISTORY
AND I LIKE THAT THERE
WAS NO GOOD RESTAURANT
IN THIS WHOLE AREA.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
FRESH INGREDIENTS
AND A LITTLE LOVE AND CARE.
I'LL HAVE
THE POT ROAST SANDWICH.
THE FLAVOR'S AMAZING,
IT'S JUST LIKE
A POT ROAST DINNER.
(Guy)
ONLY YOU EAT THIS ONE
WITH YOUR HANDS
AND LOTS OF NAPKINS.
THAT IS A BOTTOM
GOOSENECK ROUND?
BASICALLY, YES.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT ABOUT
2 1/2 TO 3-INCH SLICES.
LOOK AT THAT NICE, WHITE FAT
THAT'S GONNA RENDER DOWN.
IT'S LIKE A BRONTOSAURUS BURGER.
FRED FLINTSTONE WAS HERE.
NOW LIBERAL WITH THE SALT
AND PEPPER.
OIL ON THE GRIDDLE.
NOW IT GOES FOR A SEAR,
THREE TO FIVE MINUTES
ON EACH SIDE
BEFORE WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN THE OVEN.
IT GOES WITH
A FRIED ONION GARNISH.
OH, THOSE ARE GREAT.
AND YOU MAKE THE GRAVY FOR THIS.
BUTTER, WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE FLOUR TO THE BUTTER
AND MAKE THE ROUX.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO POUR IN
THE POT ROAST LIQUID,
WHISK IT,
ADD A LITTLE WATER,
AND THE LAST THING
IS A LITTLE BEEF BASE.
IT DOES LOOK LIKE
A FRED FLINTSTONE STEAK.
WILMA!
WHICH ONE'S GUY?
ADD A LITTLE MIREPOIX,
BAY LEAF ALL AROUND,
ADD SOME WATER,
COVER THIS, AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT IN THE OVEN AT 375
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS.
THE POT ROAST
SHOULD BE READY NOW.
NOTHING LIKE
A LITTLE POT ROAST FACIAL.
SEE HOW IT COMES APART
NICE AND EASY?
YOU DON'T THINK
IT'S NOT IMPORTANT
TO TRY IT?
LOOK AT THAT, DELICIOUS.
IT NEEDS TO TASTE GREAT
BY ITSELF
SO THE GRAVY IS
JUST ANOTHER LAYER,
IT'S NOT COVERING UP
WHAT'S NOT RIGHT.
AFTER YOU SHRED IT
YOU PUT IT IN THE AU JUS,
IT ADDS A LITTLE MORE MOISTURE
AND WARMS IT UP.
AND WHAT'S IN THAT BROTH?
THE SAME LIQUID THAT WE ROAST
THE POT ROAST IN.
THE FRIES, THE POT ROAST,
GRAVY ON EVERYTHING.
FRIED ONION RINGS,
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, HOT,
GRAVY DOWN THE FINGER.
MMM, TENDER, HOT, GREAT ROLL,
THE GRAVY'S CRAZY.
IT'S NOT JUST SOME
THICKENED BEEF STOCK.
WHAT?
MAN, CONGRATULATIONS,
THAT'S A KILLER SANDWICH.
JUICY AND TENDER.
OH, GRAVY'S AMAZING.
EVERYTHING ABOUT THIS RESTAURANT
HAS BEEN A HAPPY SURPRISE.
OUT HERE I WATCH THEM EAT
EVERY BITE
AND YOU SEE
THE SMILE ON THEIR FACE.
WHAT'S MORE REWARDING THAN THAT?
IT'S SORT OF LIKE BEING AT HOME.
(Guy)
IF YOUR MOM SPENDS ALL DAY
IN THE KITCHEN.
HOMEMADE STOCK,
SLOW-ROASTED TURKEY.
JUST LIKE YOU FIND
AT EVERY DINER.
YOU LET THIS COOL DOWN,
SO WE DON'T CUT IT
AND LOSE THE JUICES.
(Guy)
KEEPIN' IT MOIST
FOR A HUGE TURKEY CLUB.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
NO.
I AM SLOWLY RELEASING MY JAW.
I LEARNED THAT
FROM "WILD KINGDOM."
LIKE THAT.
LOOK AT THAT,
THAT IS GREAT.
TALK ABOUT DRAGGING THE TURKEY
THROUGH THE GARDEN.
(Guy)
OR HOW ABOUT
THROUGH THE GRAVY
FOR THE HOT TURKEY SANDWICH.
IT'S SUNDAY DINNER ON A PLATE,
(Guy)
SUNDAY DINNER ON A PLATE,
SCRATCH-MADE
WITH ALL THE FIXINGS,
I MEAN, ALL THE FIXINGS.
WHOLE-BERRY
CRANBERRY SAUCE.
(Guy)
IT'S ALREADY TOUGH ENOUGH
TO DO THE DINER GIG
SO YOU TO MAKE IT LESS TOUGH
ARE GONNA GO AHEAD AND MAKE
YOUR CRANBERRY SAUCE.
YES, THAT'S TRUE.
LET'S GET THIS GOING.
FRESH ORANGE JUICE,
NOW SOME FRESH CRANBERRIES,
SOME SUGAR, GROUND CINNAMON,
AND A LITTLE ALLSPICE.
WE'RE GONNA STIR IT UP,
LET IT COME UP TO A BOIL
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
I LOVE CRANBERRY RELISH.
YOU CALL IT CRANBERRY RELISH.
I DON'T COOK IT AS FAR DOWN
AS IT WOULD TURN IT INTO SAUCE,
LIKE WHAT YOU GET IN THE CAN.
I DO IT JUST UNTIL
THE CRANBERRY BURSTS.
LET THEM COOL,
THEN READY TO SERVE.
AND THEN HERE COMES THE TURKEY.
WE'RE GONNA GIVE IT
A LIGHT STEAM.
SOMEONE JUST TURNED UP
THE SLATHER FLOOD GATES.
THE MASHED POTATOES,
NOW A LITTLE GARNISH,
FRESH CRANBERRY RELISH.
THE GRAVY.
IS THAT AN OPEN-FACED MONSTER,
OR WHAT?
OH, THAT'S KILLER.
CRANBERRY GREATNESS,
LOOK AT THAT SAUCE.
YOU SHOULD SELL THAT.
OH, YOU DO,
THAT'S AWESOME.
YOU SWING THROUGH EVERY PITCH.
THANK YOU.
THE BEST THING
THAT I HAD EVER EATEN.
IT'S GOT ALL THE FLAVOR,
UNBELIEVABLE.
IT MAKES IT FEEL LIKE
THANKSGIVING EVERY DAY.
(Guy)
BUT INSTEAD OF PUMPKIN PIE...
I LOST HALF THE RECIPE
SO IT'S JUST DONUT HOLES NOW.
BUD-DA-BUMP,
BUT SERIOUSLY, JOHNNY,
HE'LL BE HERE ALL WEEK.
(Guy)
THE HOLE STORY
WHEN WE COME BACK.
TURKEY SANDWICH.
(Guy)
AT THE DEPOT DINER IN CHICAGO
VETERAN CHEF ROBERT NAVA'S
GONE FROM FINE DINING
TO FINE DINER.
IT IS COMFORT FOOD,
HOME-COOKED.
THE OPEN-FACED TURKEY SANDWICH,
THE BEST THING THAT I HAD
EVER EATEN.
POT ROAST LIKE I COULD GET
FROM MY GRANDMOTHER'S HOUSE.
(Guy)
AND JUST LIKE AT GRANDMA'S,
THEY'RE SCRATCH-MAKING
DESSERT TOO.
OH, THE MADE-TO-ORDER
MOCHA DONUTS.
THERE'S A HOMEMADE MOCHA SAUCE
THAT COMES WITH THEM
THAT'S TOPPED
WITH WHIPPED CREAM.
EGGS AND FLOUR, ALL-PURPOSE,
BAKING POWDER,
A LITTLE VANILLA,
GOOD PURE VANILLA, SUGAR.
SO AT LEAST YOU DON'T HAVE THIS
DOWN TO A COMPLETE SCIENCE.
NO, I'M STILL WINGING IT.
THEN THE MILK.
SO BEAT IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
WE LET 'EM SIT
FOR AT LEAST 30 MINUTES
BEFORE WE EVEN DARE SCOOP ONE.
THE ELASTICITY COMES OUT OF
THE GLUTEN AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
THIS IS NOT HIS FIRST RODEO.
OR DONUT BOWL.
OKAY, DOUBLE-D,
DOCTOR DINER,
WHAT ARE YOU PRESCRIBING NOW?
NOW, IT'S DONUT TIME.
IS THERE MUSIC NOW,
A DANCING DONUT?
SEE, DONUT TIME.
OKAY, DOCTOR DINER'S
GOING OFF THE DOCTOR DEEP END.
PRE-MEASURED SCOOP.
FIVE OF 'EM, WAIT A SECOND,
THEY'RE GONNA POP UP TO THE TOP.
WOW, LOOK HOW BIG THEY GET.
WHEN THEY BROWN ON BOTH SIDES,
THEY ROLL OVER?
SOMETIMES THEY DO
AND SOMETIMES THEY RESIST,
SO WE GIVE 'EM A LITTLE FLIP.
YOU JUST HAVE TO TRAIN THEM.
AS THEY EXPAND
THAT'S WHEN YOU KNOW
THEY'RE FINISHED COOKING.
HOT OIL NUGGETS
DROPPED INTO CINNAMON SUGAR.
ROLL 'EM AROUND,
GET 'EM NICE AND COATED
ON ALL SIDES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT TO MISS
A SQUARE CENTIMETER...
NO.
SOME POWDERED SUGAR
ON EVERYTHING.
VERY QUIET RIGHT NOW,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE ARE IN DONUT SURGERY.
A LITTLE CHOCOLATE SAUCE --
HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM,
SWISS CHOCOLATE AND COFFEE.
WHISK THE CHOCOLATE,
SAUCE IN THE RAMEKINS,
CREAM ON TOP.
MY SON HUNTER RIGHT NOW
IS GOING, "I SHOULD HAVE
GONE WITH YOU TO CHICAGO, DAD."
DOCTOR SAYS
IT'S READY TO GO.
TAKE TWO OF THESE
AND CALL YOU IN THE MORNING?
YES.
HOT MOLTEN SUGAR FEST.
MMM, THAT REMINDS ME OF
BEING AT THE FAIR.
IF YOU'RE GONNA GO
AND EAT SOMETHING
THIS SUGAR DOUSED
YOU MIGHT AS WELL EAT SOMETHING
THAT'S FRESH MADE AND HAND MADE
AND ALSO MADE BY A DOCTOR.
EXCELLENT, MAN.
THANK YOU.
INCREDIBLE,
ABSOLUTELY INCREDIBLE.
SUGAR EXPLOSION,
THEY ARE DELICIOUS.
MESSY, BUT SUPER WORTH IT.
WHEN YOU COME TO THE DEPOT DINER
BRING A CHANGE OF CLOTHES.
WHEN PEOPLE ARE VISITING ME
I BRING THEM HERE.
IT'S AN AMAZING PLACE.
YOU SAY TO EVERYBODY YOU KNOW,
YOU GOTTA GO TO THE DEPOT.
THIS ISN'T EVEN WORK,
THIS IS LIKE HAVING
YOUR FRIENDS COME OVER.
WE LISTEN TO MUSIC,
WE CHIT CHAT,
AND I COOK THEM
SOMETHING TO EAT.
AND THEY PAY.
SEE, IF I COULD JUST GET 'EM
TO PAY AT MY HOUSE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "D.D.D." --
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."