HI EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
WE'RE ROLLING OUT HERE IN HAWAII
FOR A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
COME ALONG
AS "TRIPLE D" GOES HAWAIIAN.
THE LOST ART OF LAULAU.
OF TYING THE LAULAU.
(Guy)
WE'RE TRACKING DOWN
THE REAL HAWAIIAN DEAL.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU LOOK NICE.
(Guy)
THE THIRD GENERATION
FAMILY FAVORITE...
DAD, I'M GONNA DO
THE WET PIPIKAULA.
(Guy)
DOING TRUE HAWAIIAN CLASSICS.
LAULAU IS A TARO LEAF,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(Guy)
AND THE ISLAND TAKE
ON BEEF JERKY.
I CAN'T WAIT TO TRY THIS.
(Guy)
THE PLACE ON THE PIER...
THIS FISH IS FRESH.
YOU'RE TALKING A FRENCH CHEF
THAT KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
(Guy)
WHERE THE SEAFOOD
REALLY IS THE CATCH OF THE DAY.
WHAT IS THIS?
MOONFISH.
(Guy)
THE HAUTE DOG JOINT...
YOU WANT TO TRY ALL OF THEM.
(Guy)
ISLAND-STYLE.
THE MOST TASTY HAUTE DOG
I'VE EVER HAD.
(Guy)
DOING SERIOUS DOGS...
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD,
VERY TASTY.
(Guy)
FROM EVERYWHERE.
YOU CAN HEAR IT SNAP.
(Guy)
AND HEY...
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE PARTY,
WHICH IS A TON OF FUN.
(Guy)
IT'S HAWAII,
WE CAN'T MISS THE LOCAL LUAU.
IT IS SO AMAZING.
(Guy)
I'VE ROASTED SOME PIG
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN IT
JUST DISINTEGRATE LIKE THAT.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE,
THAT'S GREAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
AS "TRIPLE D" GOES HAWAIIAN.
MAN, I TOLD YOU,
I'LL GO ANYWHERE
TO FIND THE FUNK.
THIS TIME ALL THE WAY TO HAWAII.
NOW YOU KNOW I LOVE THE '67,
BUT IT WON'T FLOAT,
SO THIS TIME
I'M CRUISIN' HAWAIIAN-STYLE.
CHECK OUT THE SURF WAGON.
WE'RE STARTING OUT
WITH OLD-SCHOOL HAWAIIAN COOKING
AT A PLACE CALLED HIGHWAY INN.
WELCOME TO HAWAII
AND HIGHWAY INN.
OH, THANK YOU.
ONE BUTTERFISH...
MY FAVORITE
WITH THE STEW GRAVY.
YOU DRIVE 30 MINUTES OUT HERE
JUST TO HAVE THIS.
I DRIVE 45.
LOMI AHI.
AHI FISH
WITH GREEN ONIONS,
EXCELLENT, NICE AND FRESH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
THE COCONUT CUSTARD?
THE BEST IN TOWN I'VE HAD.
THIS IS TRADITIONAL,
AUTHENTIC.
MY GRANDPARENTS STARTED IT
IN 1947, HAD SEVEN CHILDREN.
OUT OF THE SEVEN CHILDREN
SIX WORKED HERE.
(Guy)
AND REGINA TOGUCHI'S
DAD BOBBY...
DAD, I'M GONNA DO
THE WET PIPIKAULA.
(Guy)
IS STILL IN THE KITCHEN
DOING TRUE HAWAIIAN CLASSICS
THE WAY HIS DAD DID.
LAULAU IS THE TARO LEAF
WRAPPED AROUND A MEAT.
YOU CAN PUT BEEF, CHICKEN.
PORK LAULAU IS TRADITION.
AND A PIECE OF BUTTERFISH
TO ENHANCE THE FLAVOR,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SO LET'S GET INTO THIS.
WE NEED TO SALT THE PORK FIRST,
SEA SALT WE'RE USING.
AND THIS IS PORK BELLY
LIKE WE MAKE BACON OUT OF.
THIS IS A BUTTERFISH.
WHY DO THEY CALL IT BUTTERFISH?
IT'S VERY OILY, A LOT OF FAT.
BUT IT DOES ALSO HAVE A HEAD?
RIGHT.
I WOULD BE VERY SCARED
IF THAT'S HOW IT SWIMS AROUND.
SO THIS GETS FILLETED
AND SALTED.
THIS WE NEED TO SALT
ABOUT TWO WEEKS.
THEN WE CHOP IT UP?
WE CHOP IT UP.
THEN THE LEAF
FROM THE TARO PLANT.
OUT OF THIS?
THIS REALLY DOES LOOK
LIKE YOU DROVE IT OVER
IN YOUR BUICK.
WE'LL TAKE TWO LEAVES.
THE STEMS GO TOGETHER?
EITHER WAY.
SEE, YOU HAVE THEM TOGETHER,
I HAVE MINE OVER HERE
IN DING DONG LAND.
THEN WE TAKE
ABOUT FOUR PIECES OF PORK.
HE JUST JAMS IT IN THERE.
ONE FISH.
WOW, IT'S HARD.
IS THE BONE AND EVERYTHING
STILL IN IT?
YEAH, IT'LL MELT.
THE BONE WILL MELT?
YEAH.
ANOTHER LEAF.
JUST TO COVER,
MAKE IT INTO A BALL.
THEN JUST CONTINUE
TO BUILD THE BALL.
HEY, HEY,
YOU'RE WRAPPING VERY QUICKLY.
THEN YOU TAKE THE TI LEAF...
CAN YOU MAKE ACTUAL TEA
WITH THIS?
OH, NO, NO.
NO, IS THAT A TRANSLATION
IN HAWAII FOR DUMMY?
THEN YOU TAKE THE SECOND LEAF.
IT'S LIKE A TAMALE.
IT HAS BECOME A LOST ART,
HOW TO TIE THE LAULAU.
THE LOST ART OF LAULAU.
OF TYING THE LAULAU.
SO THE TYING PART
IS USING THESE TWO FINGERS HERE
THROUGH THE HOLE, UNDERNEATH,
AND YOU'VE GOT IT TIED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
HOW DID I DO?
YOU LOOK NICE.
NOW WE'VE GOT THEM MADE,
NOW WHAT DO WE DO WITH THEM?
WE NEED TO CUT THE STEMS
AND THEN THEY HAVE TO STEAM.
BIG STEAMER, DID YOU HAVE
THIS MADE JUST FOR THIS?
YES.
THEN WE START
TO LOAD THEM IN.
WE'LL MAKE A CIRCLE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY'RE ALL GONNA FIT.
THAT'S A LOT.
AND HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA GO IN THE STEAMER?
TWO HOURS.
TWO HOURS, SO ARE WE DONE?
SO WE NEED TO OPEN THIS.
THIS THING'S GONNA BE HOT.
IT SMELLS LIKE LEAVES,
WOW, IT'S GONNA BE NUTS.
I WILL UNWRAP IT FOR YOU.
OKAY.
(Guy)
IS IT GONNA TASTE BETTER
THAN IT LOOKS, YOU TELL ME.
IT TASTES MUCH,
MUCH BETTER.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD,
THE FAT REALLY MELLOWS IT OUT
AND YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
AMOUNT OF SALT IN THERE,
I LOVE IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF
A SPINACH TEXTURE TO IT.
THIS IS MORE GREENS
THAN I'VE HAD THIS MONTH.
I'M DOWN WITH THE WHOLE THING.
NOW WHAT'S THIS STUFF HERE,
POI SERVED COLD?
YEAH.
IT LOOKS LIKE PUDDING.
IT'S THE ROOT OF THE TARO.
TRY IT, YOU'LL LIKE IT.
HERE WE GO.
THAT'S FUNKY,
IT TASTES LIKE YOGURT.
IT'S BETWEEN LIKE A GREEK YOGURT
AND A REGULAR YOGURT.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
SOURNESS TO IT,
BUT WHEN YOU ADD
THE SALTINESS OF THE PORK
AND THE HERBACEOUSNESS OF
THE TARO,
THAT COMBO RIGHT THERE,
REALLY GOOD.
LAULAU POI.
VERY MOIST, STILL IN THE LEAF,
IT'S PERFECT.
POI WAS REALLY THE STAPLE FOOD
OF THE NATIVE HAWAIIAN PEOPLE.
THEY STAY TRUE
TO THE ISLAND STYLE
OF MAKING THINGS.
THE FOOD HASN'T CHANGED,
IT'S STILL THE SAME
HOMEMADE STUFF.
LOMI AHI.
FRESH AHI.
WHY THE ICE CUBE,
KEEP IT NICE AND COOL?
THIS IS AS TRADITIONAL
AS IT COMES?
YES.
(Guy)
FROM A TRIPE STEW...
REGINA'S GOT ME HOOKED ON THIS.
(Guy)
TO SQUID LUAU...
MIXED WITH COCONUT MILK
AND TARO PLANT.
IT'S THE MOST DELICIOUS THING.
(Guy)
AND THE NUMBER ONE ITEM
ON THE MENU...
DOUBLE PIPIKAULA, HALF THAT.
IT'S A SMOKED TYPE OF MEAT,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
PIPIKAULA,
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
DRIED BEEF.
AND I JUST THOUGHT
IT WAS CALLED BEEF JERKY.
SO WE'VE GOT A BIG CHUCK ROLL,
SLICE IT ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
CAN I SEE THAT THING,
THAT'S A KNIFE.
YOU MARINATE IT,
SPRINKLE IN SOME SALT.
AND WHAT ARE WE PUTTING IN HERE,
IS THIS SOY?
SHOYU.
JAPANESE WORD FOR IT.
SHOYU, SOY SAUCE,
EITHER WAY IT'S THE SAME THING.
NO.
SO LAYER AFTER LAYER.
THEN WE HANG IT TO DRY.
DO WE HAVE A SMOKER
OR WHERE ARE WE GONNA HANG IT?
ABOVE OUR STOVES.
IS THAT WHAT THE WIRE'S FOR?
YES.
YOU CAN'T SAY
YOU GET TO DO THAT EVERY DAY.
(Guy)
HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA BE UP HERE?
FOUR HOURS OR SO.
THIS RIGHT HERE,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS HISTORY.
NOW IT'S STARTING
TO RELEASE ITS MOISTURE.
MEAT RAIN IN FLAVOR TOWN.
I CAN'T WAIT TO TRY THIS.
(Guy)
NOW WHAT HAPPENS
AFTER IT HANGS?
I FRY IT LIKE A STEAK,
PUT SOME OIL ON IT.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
ON THE FLAT TOP AND
CHOP IT UP.
EVERYDAY YOU SEE THIS.
HANGING IT OVER THE GRILL,
CUTTING IT ON THE FLAT TOP.
NONE OF THIS IS MAKING SENSE.
MMM, WOW.
IT KIND OF REMINDS ME OF
DRY-AGED BEEF, A LITTLE SALTIER.
IT KIND OF GIVES ME A FEELING OF
LIKE, WET BEEF JERKY,
THE RICHNESS OF IT,
ITS DEEP FLAVOR.
HOW IS IT AGAIN?
PIPIKAULA.
SOMETHING I'VE NEVER HAD BEFORE.
JUST HANGING IT
OVER THE STOVE THING, FUNKY.
CAPITAL "F" FUNKY.
THE MOST FLAVORFUL PIPIKAULA
I'VE EVER HAD.
I LIKE IT CRISPY,
I LIKE THE FAT.
IT IS VERY SOFT,
BUT IT ALSO HAS
A SMOKED FLAVOR.
EVERYBODY CAN NOW TASTE
A LITTLE BIT OF HAWAII.
TWO LAULAUS PLEASE.
IT'S 52 YEARS OF
A FAMILY TRADITION
THAT WE'VE TRIED TO KEEP ALIVE.
THE HAWAIIAN FOOD HERE
IS UNBEATABLE.
AND THE PEOPLE
MAKE YOU FEEL LIKE OHANA.
IN HAWAIIAN WE SAY OHANA,
FAMILY IS IMPORTANT.
WELL I FEEL LIKE I'M PART OF
THE FAMILY NOW.
(Guy)
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADED TO THE WATER
FOR SOME OF THE FRESHEST
OF WHAT HAWAII DOES BEST.
LOOK AT THAT,
YOU HAVE GOT TO BE KIDDING ME.
IT'S THE BEST FISH
YOU WANT TO EAT ON THE ISLAND.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
SO HERE I AM
ON HONOLULU HARBOR.
NOW THIS IS WHERE
ALL THE FISHING BOATS COME IN,
DROP OFF THEIR CATCH,
AND THEN GO TO AUCTION.
NOW RESTAURANTS
IN INDUSTRIAL AREAS LIKE THIS
ARE USUALLY A HIT OR A MISS.
BUT FROM WHAT I HEAR
NICO'S AT PIER 38 IS A HOME RUN.
THE BEST FISH YOU WANT TO EAT
ON THE ISLAND.
THIS FISH IS FRESH.
YOU'RE TALKING A FRENCH CHEF
WHO KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
THREE MEDIUM-WELL.
(Guy)
THAT WOULD BE FRENCH-BORN OWNER
NICO CHAIZE,
WHO'S SERIOUS ABOUT ONLY SERVING
THE FRESHEST SEAFOOD.
THIS GUY'S BUYING
FRESH FISH RIGHT HERE...
(Guy)
AT 5:30 IN THE MORNING
AT THE AUCTION HOUSE
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET.
OH NICE.
(Nico)
THIS IS WHERE ALL THE FISH
CAUGHT IN HAWAIIAN WATERS
GET UNLOADED
AND SOLD THE SAME DAY.
IS THIS AWESOME, OR WHAT?
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES"
AND FISH MARKET.
THIS IS CRAZY.
YEAH.
WHAT IS THIS?
THAT IS A BIG MARLIN,
THAT'S A BIG MAHI-MAHI.
WHAT IS THAT ONE?
THIS ONE IS OPAH, OR MOONFISH.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF IT.
IT CAN GO UP TO 150 POUNDS.
NOW WILL THEY BREAK IT DOWN
FOR YOU?
YES, THEY'LL TAKE CARE OF IT.
THAT IS GOING TO BE
OUR SPECIAL TODAY.
LOOK AT THAT,
YOU HAVE GOT TO BE KIDDING ME.
THAT IS THE LOIN OF OPAH,
THAT IS THE BASE PART.
BACK TO THE RESTAURANT?
YEAH, BACK TO THE RESTAURANT.
(Guy)
WHERE NICO'S
PUTTING HIS OWN TWIST
ON THIS HAWAIIAN FAVORITE.
OPAH WITH CRAB STUFFING.
(Guy)
AND SCRATCH-MADE
WATERCRESS CREAM SAUCE.
FANTASTIC.
SO WE'VE GOT
THE OPAH READY TO GO.
I'LL TAKE THE SKIN OFF
AND FROM THERE I'LL CUT
A SEVEN-OUNCE PORTION.
IT'S A PRETTY FIRM FISH.
PRETTY MOIST,
OPAH'S REALLY WET.
OKAY, SO NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA FILL IT UP
WITH OUR CRAB STUFFING.
I'VE GOT ONION, CELERY, GARLIC,
SAUTE IN OLIVE OIL.
WE DEGLAZE IT IN A WHITE WINE
AND FRESH THYME WILL BE ADDED.
SMASH IT UP, DIJON MUSTARD,
CAYENNE PEPPER, AND HEAVY CREAM.
SOME PANKO AT THE END
TO THICKEN IT UP.
SO 15 MINUTES IN THE FRIDGE
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
THE FILET'S SO THIN,
HOW ARE YOU GONNA STUFF IT?
I'M GONNA GO ON THE TOP
AND CUT IT ALL THE WAY DOWN.
THEN STUFF IT
WITH OUR CRAB MEAT.
SO YOU'RE DOING AN OPEN FACE?
AN OPEN FACE, YEAH.
NICE SEASONING
WITH WHITE PEPPER AND SALT.
(Nico)
OLIVE OIL, WE ADD THE FISH,
CRAB-SIDE DOWN FIRST.
QUICK BOTH SIDES,
FINISH IT IN THE OVEN?
IN TEN MINUTES
IT WILL BE READY.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A WATERCRESS CREAM SAUCE.
SOME OLIVE OIL, ONIONS,
GARLIC, DRIED THYME,
WHOLE LEMON, PEELED.
WHITE WINE.
YOU HAVE THE TV HAND,
THE POUR.
I ADD IN CHICKEN STOCK.
THAT'S REDUCED DOWN,
NOW WE ADD THE CREAM?
(Nico)
IT'S DONE,
NOW TO THICKEN IT.
STRAIN IT,
INTO THE BLENDER.
ARE YOU STRONG?
OH YEAH.
NICE FRESH WATERCRESS.
PUT THE WHOLE THING DOWN.
JALAPENOS.
JALAPENO.
JALA-PEENO.
JALAPENO, IT'S PAIN-O.
A BIG GREEN THING.
PUT THE LID ON IT.
YOU'RE GONNA BLEND IT
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
LET'S GET THE OPAH
OUT OF THE OVEN.
IT JUST DOESN'T LOOK RIGHT
PUTTING IT INTO
A TO-GO CONTAINER.
THE WATERCRESS SAUCE
RIGHT OVER THE FISH.
MMM, CRAZY GOOD.
THAT BITE RIGHT THERE,
THAT'S A MILLION DOLLAR
MONEY BITE.
THE WATERCRESS
WITH THE JALAPENOS IN IT
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
I THINK
I COULD TAKE SOME OF THIS,
SMEAR IT ON THAT LID,
AND THEN EAT LID.
THE STUFFING IS DYNAMITE TOO,
DUDE, I MEAN IT'S...
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE.
(lightening and thunder)
YOU HEAR THAT,
THUNDER FROM THE HEAVENS.
WHAT?
GRILLED OPAH
WITH WATERCRESS CREAM SAUCE.
IT'S FRESH AND IT'S LIGHT.
IT HAS THE PERFECT TEXTURE,
THE PERFECT TASTE.
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
(Guy)
AND THE WORD'S GETTING OUT.
YOU KNOW WHAT, YOU GOTTA
GET HERE BEFORE LUNCH
OR COME IN AFTER.
(Guy)
'CAUSE NICO'S CRANKING OUT
500 ORDERS A DAY.
YOU GET FIVE-STAR QUALITY
FOR ROCK-BOTTOM PRICES.
IF YOU WENT TO A RESTAURANT
IT WOULD COST LIKE, 30.
THAT DISH RIGHT THERE
WOULD BE $30, I AGREE.
EVERYTHING IS $7.00?
YEAH, THE GOAL
IS TO BE UNDER $10.00.
I CAN GO TO A BURGER SHOP
AND END UP SPENDING MORE.
(Guy)
AND STILL NOT END UP
WITH THE DOUBLE-PATTY
MARLIN BURGER.
HOW'S YOUR BURGER?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FRESH MARLIN BURGER, OKAY.
SO WE HAVE FRESH MARLIN CUBED,
THIS IS A STRIPED MARLIN.
PUT THE MARLIN
IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR
AND BLEND IT.
OH, WE'RE REALLY
BREAKING IT DOWN, HUH?
BREAKING IT DOWN,
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
YOU AND THE FRENCH AND THE PATE.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE THAT.
SO WE'VE GOT THE GROUND-UP
STRIPED MARLIN.
FINE-DICED ONIONS,
FRESH GRATED GARLIC,
DIJON MUSTARD,
DRIED DILL WEED.
THAT GIVES A LOT OF FLAVOR
AND FRESHNESS.
DUDE, HOW MUCH
DID YOU JUST PUT IN THERE?
A LOT.
SALT AND WHITE PEPPER.
MARLIN AND DILL SANDWICH.
TABASCO, SOME OLIVE OIL,
HOMEMADE TARTAR SAUCE.
LEMON ZEST,
THE JUICE OUT OF TWO LEMONS.
LIME ZEST, LIME JUICE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX IT.
SO NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
PORTION IT ON COATED WAX PAPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA SMASH IT DOWN
TO MAKE THE PATTIES.
(Nico)
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE HAMBURGER BUNS.
OIL FIRST, THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE MARLIN BURGER DOWN,
TWO PATTIES.
YOU GET A LOT OF CRISPINESS.
BOTH SIDES, MEDIUM-RARE.
(Nico)
SQUEEZE ON YOUR AIOLI FIRST,
BUTTER LETTUCE, RED ONION,
TOMATO AND TWO PATTIES
AND THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT,
NOW THAT'S A BIG BURGER.
DUDE, THAT'S THE MOST TENDER
SEAFOOD BURGER I'VE EVER HAD.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
COMING OUT OF THAT.
THAT SMOKES ANY FAST FOOD.
I WOULD ORDER THAT AGAIN
WITHOUT QUESTION.
THE DOUBLE PATTY...
THE GUY GETS IT.
IT'S DEFINITELY HEARTY,
YET LIGHT.
AND CHEAP.
YOU KNOW IT'S LOCAL,
YOU KNOW THE FISH IS FRESH.
NICO'S...
MMM, NUMBER ONE.
(Guy)
YOU'RE A KNOCK-OUT CHEF,
THE FOOD TASTES OUTRAGEOUS,
AND THE PRICES
COULDN'T BE ANY BETTER.
THIS WAS A REALLY GREAT VISIT.
YOU GOTTA COME SEE THIS CAT.
NEXT UP I'M HEADED
FOR A TRUE HAWAIIAN CLASSIC.
YOU GOT IT, HOT DOGS.
FANTASTIC, YOU'RE IN PARADISE
AND YOU'RE HEATING HOT DOGS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YOU KNOW ON "TRIPLE D"
WE LOVE TO FIND
THE-FISH-OUT-WATER SITUATIONS.
WELL HERE WE ARE IN HONOLULU
AND GET THIS.
A DUDE FROM CHICAGO
WHO'S PARENTS WERE
BORN IN HAWAII
IS BRINGING HIS CHICAGO DOG
TO HAWAII WITH A LITTLE
SOMETHING, SOMETHING.
THIS IS HANK'S HAUTE DOGS.
ONE CHICAGO,
ONE LOBSTER DOG
AND A FRY FOR HERE.
POLISH FAT BOY IN HAWAII.
IT'S FANTASTIC,
YOU'RE IN PARADISE
AND YOU'RE EATING HOT DOGS.
(Guy)
'CAUSE WHEN HANK ADANIYA
MOVED TO PARADISE,
HE JUST HAD TO
START SERVING UP THE DOGS.
HOT DOGS WERE IN MY BLOOD
AND MY FAMILY WAS FROM HERE.
(Guy)
HIS PARENTS RAN A HOTDOG JOINT
HERE IN THE '50s.
NOW IT'S HANK'S TURN
WITH A PLACE OF HIS OWN.
AND HIS TOP SELLER...
TWO CHICAGO COMING AT YOU.
(Guy)
IS THE ONE HE BROUGHT
FROM THE WINDY CITY.
SO WE'RE GONNA DO
A CHICAGO DOG.
WE SHIP THESE BUNS
IN FROM CHICAGO
BECAUSE THAT'S THE ONLY PLACE
I CAN GET A POPPY SEED BUN.
VIENNA, ALL-BEEF,
NATURAL-CASING DOGS.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT THING.
SEVEN CONDIMENTS.
YELLOW MUSTARD...
I THINK HE'S DONE THAT BEFORE.
ONION.
THE FULL NEON RELISH.
THIS TOO GETS SHIPPED IN.
TOMATO, PICKLE,
SPORT PEPPERS.
I HAVE TO GET THOSE
FROM CHICAGO.
WE CALL THIS DRAGGING THE DOG
THROUGH THE GARDEN.
YOU GOT IT.
AND CELERY SALT, VOILA.
THIS IS GOING TO BE HOT.
I THINK YOU CAN HANDLE IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT WAS BEST ABOUT IT,
YOU COULD HEAR IT SNAP.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
COMING OUT OF THAT.
THAT IS THE REAL DEAL,
NICE JOB.
I'VE HAD THE CHICAGO DOG
AND THAT WAS GREAT.
YOU'VE DONE ABOUT FOUR
DIFFERENT TYPES OF HOT DOGS?
WE DID.
I HAVE ENJOYED EVERY ONE,
ALL OF THEM WERE DELICIOUS.
THE ACCOUTERMENTS ON THEM
ARE DIFFERENT.
(Guy)
AND SCRATCH MADE.
GARLIC AIOLI.
MANGO RELISH,
THAT'S REALLY AWESOME.
WASABI MAYONNAISE.
CURRY KETCHUP,
PRETTY TANGY.
(Guy)
AND THIS ONE
MANGO MUSTARD
WITH AN ISLAND TWIST.
IT GOES ON
OUR HAWAIIAN-STYLE HOTDOG.
START WITH SOME BROWN MUSTARD
AND THEN WE ADD SOME
MANGO PUREE.
LIME JUICE HERE,
SOME HONEY.
HONEY, I LIKE
WHERE THIS IS GOING.
AND THEN A LITTLE LIME ZEST.
BLEND IT ALL TOGETHER
AND HE'S GOING AT IT.
I GOTTA TRY IT.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
THAT'S REALLY ANOTHER
SPOON-NECESSARY NICE.
MMM.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE SO FAR?
I THINK THE HAWAIIAN.
THE HAWAIIAN DOG.
PICK UP THE HAWAIIAN.
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
VERY TASTY.
THE CHICKEN HOTDOG
IS REALLY GOOD.
FAT BOY.
(Guy)
A VERSION OF THE B.L.T.
GREAT CRUNCH,
BACON ADDS IT.
YOU GOT THE PIG AND THE DOG
RUNNING THROUGH THE GARDEN
ON THAT ONE.
A LOT OF DIFFERENT VARIETY HERE.
(Guy)
AND THAT'S JUST
THE REGULAR MENU.
EACH DAY OF THE WEEK
WE DO A SPECIAL DOG.
TUESDAYS WE HAVE ALLIGATOR,
WEDNESDAYS IS RABBIT AND VEAL.
WHAT WE DID WAS SAY,
"LET'S TRY INTRODUCING SOME OF
THESE REALLY GOURMET DOGS."
FRIDAYS IS LOBSTER DOG.
PROBABLY OUR
MOST POPULAR SPECIAL.
YOU START
BY PUREEING THE SEAFOOD.
BAY SCALLOPS.
YOU'VE GOT TUB-O-GROUND-OF-FISH.
YES, MMM-HMM.
TAKE THESE OUT
AND MOVE TO THE SHRIMP.
IT'S LIKE A DEVEIN
AND DE-SHELL 21 TO 25.
MASH IT UP GOOD.
LOBSTER TIME, I WANT THAT ONE
FAIRLY ROUGH TO GIVE IT TEXTURE,
WE CAN FEEL THE LOBSTER
IN THE SAUSAGE.
A LITTLE ONION THAT HAS BEEN
SAUTED WITH GARLIC.
CARROT, SHREDDED,
A LITTLE GREEN ONION.
NOW COMES THE SURIMI --
A TUB OR TWO OF FISH PASTE.
IT REALLY TIGHTENS IT UP.
GOT A LITTLE BIT OF NOSE
TO IT, DOESN'T IT?
IT'S KIND OF LIKE SOMEONE
DROVE THROUGH THE OCEAN
WITH A BIG OL' BLENDER.
(imitating blender noise)
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MAYONNAISE
THAT WE'RE GOING TO SEASON
THE SAUSAGE WITH.
BECAUSE YOU'VE GOTTA HAVE
SOME FAT IN THERE.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
A LITTLE MAYONNAISE,
HALF-AND-HALF.
LOBSTER BASE, NOT MUCH,
IT REALLY IS PRETTY POWERFUL.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER, THYME,
FINALLY SOME WHITE PEPPER.
SO WE'VE GOT QUITE A MIX GOING.
YEAH, WE DO.
NEXT IS A LITTLE BIT OF
PORK CASING.
THREAD THIS ON.
FOLKS, IF LOOK AT HIS FORM
THAT HE'S PRESENTING HERE,
THE THUMB
AND WITH THE HAND CRANKING.
HE'S ALSO VERY GOOD
AT RUBBING THE TUMMY
AND PATTING THE HEAD NEXT.
THAT LOOKS ABOUT RIGHT.
NOW WE'LL JUST
TWIST THESE LINKS OFF.
I'M GLAD YOU PUT THE FAT IN IT,
THAT'LL MAKE IT NICE AND CREAMY.
WHEN WE'RE ALL SAID AND DONE
WE GO INTO SOME BOILING WATER.
THAT WILL KIND OF POACH 'EM.
HIT 'EM INTO AN ICE BATH
TO STOP THE COOKING PROCESS.
CHILL 'EM DOWN, YES,
AND WE'LL HOLD 'EM.
THEN WHEN WE'RE READY
WE'LL GO AHEAD AND SEAR 'EM OFF
INTO SOME BUTTER.
WE FOUND THAT BY SEARING IT
YOU CAN GET THAT CRUNCH AGAIN
OFF OF THAT CASING.
I THINK WE'VE GOT THIS ONE
SAUTED UP.
WE JUST LET IT SIT
IN CLARIFIED BUTTER.
LET'S MAKE IT.
PRISTINE BUN,
LOTS OF SAUSAGE,
A LITTLE GARLIC AIOLI,
VERY GREEN RELISH.
THE NEON.
FOR A LITTLE ASIAN FLARE
WE HAVE SOME PICKLED
DAIKON RELISH.
MMM, GOOD LOBSTER.
THERE'S GOOD TEXTURE TO IT,
THE RELISH AND THE DAIKON
PLAY IN FOR A LITTLE CRUNCH.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU,
IF YOU WANT TO HAVE
A UNIQUE DOG EXPERIENCE
THAT'S THE DOG YOU WANT.
NICE JOB, MAN.
BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S TO DIE FOR.
JUST THE MOST TASTY HOTDOG
I'VE EVER HAD.
ANDOUILLE DOGS.
I WANT TO TRY ALL OF THEM.
SO 60 SECONDS ON THE POLISH.
THIS IS MY NUMBER ONE SPOT.
WATCH OUT,
THE HOTDOG KING RIGHT HERE.
THE CAPTAIN OF ENCASED MEATS.
NEXT UP WE'RE GOING TO A PARTY
WHERE THEY'RE ROASTING A PIG
IN THE GROUND.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE, MMM.
THIS IS THE REAL STUFF.
IT'S LUAU TIME
WHEN WE GET BACK.
SO WHEN WE DECIDED
TO VISIT HAWAII ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES"
ONE THING WE HAD TO CHECK OUT
WAS A LUAU.
SO I GUESS NOW YOU CAN CALL IT
"TRIPLE D AND L."
SO HERE WE ARE,
TIME TO HIT THE BEACH
AT GERMAINE'S LUAU.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE PARTY,
WHICH IS A TON OF FUN.
(Guy)
EVEN WHEN YOU LIVE ON THE ISLAND
YOU STILL COME TO A LUAU?
I STILL COME TO A LUAU.
(Guy)
AND THIS ONE'S THE REAL DEAL.
IT IS SO AMAZING.
(Guy)
WHERE THE LOCALS GO.
I AM FROM HAWAII,
THIS IS THE REAL STUFF.
(Guy)
AND THE CENTERPIECE OF
ANY GOOD LUAU...
JUST PORK.
KALUA PIG.
THEY COOK IT IN AN IMU
WHICH IS UNDERGROUND.
PLACE THE PIG INTO THE IMU
FOR ABOUT EIGHT HOURS.
THE PIT'S CALLED THE IMU.
THE PIT IS CALLED THE IMU.
(Guy)
SCOTT HARADA SHOULD KNOW.
HIS FAMILY'S BUSINESS
MARIAN'S CATERING
HAS BEEN DOING
LUAUS AT GERMAINE'S
FOR OVER 30 YEARS.
THIS IS A GOOD-LOOKING HOG.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU SPLIT IT DOWN THE CENTER,
OPEN IT UP SO YOU CAN GET
ALL THE SMOKE INTO HERE
AND THE TEMPERATURE IN HERE.
WHAT TIME
DID YOU START THE FIRE?
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
IT TAKES ABOUT TWO HOURS
FOR THE ROCKS TO COME UP
TO TEMPERATURE.
SO THE CHARCOAL GOES AWAY,
THE ROCKS STAY SUPER HOT.
I DIG IT,
LET'S SEE IT.
(Scott)
SO WE'VE GOT MIKE COMING IN
WITH HAWAIIAN SEA SALT,
SALT THAT'S DRIED OUT
FROM THE OCEAN WATER OVER HERE.
SO THEY'RE GENEROUS WITH IT.
VERY GENEROUS.
NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
SOME OF THESE HOT ROCKS
ARE GONNA BE PLACED IN
THE CAVITY OF THE PIG.
WE CAN COOK IT
FROM THE OUTSIDE IN
AS WELL AS FROM THE INSIDE OUT.
OH, YOU CAN HEAR
THE FAT SNAPPING AND POPPING.
IT SMELLS GOOD, HUH GUY?
IT SMELLS FANTASTIC.
SO HE'S GETTING
A NEW PIECE OF CHICKEN WIRE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA BRING IN
THE STALK OF THE BANANA TREE.
IT HOLDS A LOT OF
HIGH-WATER CONTENT
SO THAT'S WHAT WE USE
TO IMPART FLAVOR AS WELL
AS THE MOISTURE.
(Guy)
NOW THE CHICKEN WIRE.
WE'LL PLACE THE PIG ON TOP.
WHOA, THAT ALMOST DIDN'T FIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THE LARGER
PIECES OF BANANA STUMP OVER IT
TO SEAL IT UP FROM THE TOP.
HE'S GONNA BUILD A LITTLE HOUSE.
RIGHT.
NOW WE GO WITH THE LEAVES,
A WET BURLAP SACK.
THIS IS
A MODERN DAY IMPLEMENTATION.
IT SEALS MUCH BETTER.
TRADITIONALLY IT WAS
ALL BANANA LEAVES ON TOP.
WE WILL ALSO LAY
OUR FINAL TARP OVER IT.
WOW, A LOT OF WORK,
ANYTHING GO UP ON TOP OF THIS?
IT WILL BE COMPLETELY COVERED
WITH SAND.
EIGHT HOURS.
EIGHT HOURS OF LOVE.
EIGHT HOURS,
BETTER BE SOME GOOD PIG.
YES.
IS THERE A CEREMONY
WHEN THIS COMES OUT?
YES.
(Luau host)
'EKAHI ONE, 'ELUA TWO,
'EKOLU THREE,
OKAY, KALUA PUA'A.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THERE YOU HAVE IT,
OUR HAWAIIAN-STEAMED PIG.
I'VE ROASTED SOME PIG,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN IT
JUST DISINTEGRATE LIKE THAT.
PUT SOME MORE SALT ON IT.
I LIKE HOW YOU SHOW UP
AT THE LAST MINUTE.
THESE CATS HAVE BEEN...
THE GOOD-LOOKING GUYS
GET THE HARD WORK.
I'LL TRY THAT RIGHT THERE.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SEA SALT ON IT,
NICE SUBTLE FLAVOR.
OH, IT'S KILLER,
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA LIKE THIS.
(woman)
THE SMOKINESS
THAT COMES THROUGH
IS SO INCREDIBLE.
THE BEST EVER.
THE FOOD IS GREAT, I ATE
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
AMAZING FOOD
AND AMAZING HULA DANCERS.
BEING ON THE BEACH,
SEEING PEOPLE OUT HERE
ENJOYING THEMSELVES.
IT DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER.
IT'S HOME.
VERY NICE, GREAT JOB.
ALL RIGHT.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THE "TRIPLE D"
HAWAIIAN VACATION.
TIME FOR ME
TO HEAD BACK TO THE MAINLAND,
PICK UP THE CAMARO
AND HIT THE ROAD
LOOKING FOR MORE OF AMERICA'S
GREATEST DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES.
'TIL NEXT TIME, ALOHA.