HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
CHICKEN WINGS.
HOME...
TRADITIONAL BUFFALO FOOD.
AND AWAY.
IT'S WEINER SCHNITZEL.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IN CHICAGO...
THIS IS ABOUT READY.
A TASTE OF PERU...
SPICY SHRIMP, EXCELLENT.
AT A TASTE OF PERU.
WE'RE READY TO PUT IT
ON THE PLATE, OKAY?
HERE YOU GO.
A GERMAN BAKERY...
(man) WHEAT AND WHITE.
IN OKLAHOMA...
I LOVE THE BREAD.
I LOVE THE PIE.
COOKING UP THE CLASSICS.
WHETHER IT'S THE BRATWURST
OR THE SCHNITZEL...
SCHNITZEL IN THE WINDOW.
TOPFLIGHT EVERY TIME.
AND BAKING 'EM, TOO.
THE RYE BREAD
IS WONDERFUL.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME.
A WESTERN NEW YORK JOINT...
YOU CAN GET ANYTHING YOU WANT
HERE, AND YOU'D BE HAPPY.
DOING FAVORITES
FROM AROUND THE CORNER...
(woman) BEEF ON WECK.
THE PERFECT SANDWICH.
AND ACROSS THE POND.
(woman) IRISH BEER CHEDDAR.
THANK YOU.
MMM. WOW, THAT'S BIG,
DEEP, RICH FLAVOR.
WHAT KIND OF HOT SAUCE
IS THAT?
WING SAUCE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M ON THE NORTHEAST SIDE
OF CHICAGO
IN ONE OF THE MOST DIVERSE
ZIP CODES IN THE WORLD,
SO I'M TOLD,
AND THE QUESTION IS--
WHAT DO I WANT TO EAT?
DO I WANT DINE-IN?
DO I WANT TAKEOUT?
DO I WANT EXPENSIVE,
INEXPENSIVE?
DO I WANT CHINESE, ITALIAN,
MEXICAN, AMERICAN?
I MEAN, I JUST DON'T KNOW.
SO I THINK IT'S TIME THAT
I TOOK SOME GREAT ADVICE
FROM MY FRIEND MARIA
AND TRY SOME PERUVIAN FOOD.
AND THAT BRINGS ME HERE
TO TASTE OF PERU.
CAMARONES A LA DIABLA.
SPICY SHRIMP OVER A BED OF RICE.
IT WAS EXCELLENT.
PESTO SPAGHETTI, IT GOES
ON THE POUNDED-OUT STEAK.
THIS IS ABOUT READY.
SEAFOOD SALAD--OCTOPUS,
SEA BASS, IT WAS EXCELLENT.
WHAT IS THIS,
A PERUVIAN SMORGASBORD?
IT'S LIKE THAI, ITALIAN, MEXICAN
AND THEN SOUTH AMERICAN. UNIQUE.
AND IT'S ALL THE STUFF
CESAR IZQUIERDO
GREW UP LOVING IN PERU.
MY MOM, SHE TAUGHT ME
HOW TO COOK ALL THE FOOD.
TEN MINUTES MORE.
NOW HE'S SHARING HIS FAVORITES
AT HIS OWN JOINT.
HEY, BOBBY,
HOW YOU DOING?
IT MAKES ME VERY PROUD WHEN
PEOPLE COME ENJOY OUR FOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(man) TAMALE READY.
HIS TAMALES ARE BY FAR THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
TYPICAL TAMALE
YOU CAN GET IN PERU.
WRAPPED IN BANANA LEAVES,
NOT CORN HUSKS.
OKAY, SO LET'S GO, BABY.
OKAY.
CORN FLOUR AND...
RICE FLOUR.
YES.
RICE FLOUR?
YES. TRUST ME.
PERUVIAN FOOD HAS THAT
MULTICULTURAL BLEND, OKAY.
MIX IT UP SO WE CAN MAKE
OUR MASA DOUGH FOR THE TAMALES.
NOW WE'RE SET TO START
COOKING THE OIL.
WE PUT THE ACHIOTE.
THE ANNATTO SEED,
NO FLAVOR.
COLOR THE OIL, IT'LL MAKE
THIS REAL VIBRANT RED HUE.
STRAIN THE SEEDS OUT.
PUT IT IN THE MASA.
LOOK AT THAT COLOR.
OH, IT'S AWESOME.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HEAT UP
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL,
ONIONS, GARLIC PASTE.
IS THIS GONNA GO
IN THE MASA?
YES.
ANCHO CHILI PASTE.
SO THE MASA'S GONNA
HAVE FLAVORING?
THAT'S CORRECT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT
I'VE SEEN THAT BEFORE.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
SEE IT NOW.
NOW THIS IS
THE CHICKEN BOUILLON.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
NOW ALL WE DO IS WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF CHICKEN STOCK.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
AND YOU LET THAT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER.
RIGHT.
WE'RE READY HERE
TO START THE STRAINING PROCESS.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
PRETTY SOON WE'LL START
MAKING THE TAMALES.
YOU EVER MAKE A TAMALE?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I KNOW YOU HAVE.
(speaking indistinctly)
CAN I TASTE THIS?
SURE.
JUST GIVE ME
A BOWL OF THAT.
NO, IT'S GOT
TO BE COOKED.
GONNA ADD SOME BANANA LEAVES.
ONE SPOONFUL IN HERE.
GONNA PUT THE CHICKEN,
LITTLE PIECE OF HOT PEPPER,
A COUPLE OF PEANUTS,
THE OLIVE.
AND YOU TOP IT OFF
WITH ANOTHER SPOONFUL.
THIS IS A TRICK.
YOU GO LIKE THIS.
SO AS OPPOSED TO USING
THE CORN HUSK,
YOU'RE USING THE TINFOIL
TO WORK AS THE HUSK
AND GETTING A LITTLE BIT
OF FLAVOR AND SOME BARRIER
FROM THE BANANA LEAF.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL IT.
IT HAS TO STAY IN FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR, HOUR AND A HALF.
WOW.
SO THOSE BAD BOYS
ARE BOILING.
ALL RIGHT.
THEY HAVEN'T LEAKED.
NO, THEY HAVEN'T.
IT'S LIKE A PERUVIAN
HOT POCKET. WOW.
AND WHAT DO WE SERVE
WITH IT?
SALSA CRIOLLA.
IT'S SLICE ONIONS, OLIVE OIL,
VINEGAR AND LIME.
NOW YOU'RE READY.
MMM. THAT'S AWESOME.
IT'S THE BEST MASA
I'VE EVER TRIED.
YEAH?
I THINK THAT'S
'CAUSE OF THE RICE FLOUR.
ALL COOKED DOWN NICE AND TENDER,
TONS OF FLAVOR IN IT. MMM.
WELL, THE VINEGAR ONION GIDDYAP
HERE, THAT WORKS BIG-TIME.
THAT'S KILLER.
(woman) VERY MOIST,
NOT TOO SPICY,
JUST THE PERFECT HINT
OF HOT PEPPERS IN THERE.
I LOVE IT.
MY WIFE TAKES THEM HOME.
SHE LOVES THEM SO MUCH.
THAT'S WHAT BRINGS ME BACK.
CHUPE DE CAMARONES.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
BUT A GREAT MEAL HERE.
UNA SOPA DE VIAGRA.
DO PEOPLE KNOW
WHAT PERUVIAN FOOD IS?
IT'S STILL REVEALING ITSELF
TO THE WORLD.
ONE DISH AT A TIME...
COMING OUT IN A SECOND.
WITH CESAR'S HELP.
ALL RIGHT.
FROM PAELLA TO CEVICHE...
OUTSTANDING FLAVOR.
AND SOMETHING CALLED
ANTICUCHOS.
IT'S BEEF HEART.
YEP, BEEF HEART.
EVERY PERUVIAN EATS THIS.
OH, BOY.
THE TASTE,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I'M JUST ENJOYING
THIS ONE BITE.
I'M JUST--IT'S SO GOOD I DON'T
EVEN WANT TO SWALLOW IT YET.
(laughs)
BUT IF YOU DON'T HAVE
THE HEART FOR HEART,
THEY ARE USING
THE REST OF THE COW...
MMM.
LIKE THIS TRUE
PERUVIAN CLASSIC...
LOMO SALTADO.
KIND OF LIKE A BEEF STIR-FRY
WITH FRENCH FRIES.
LOMO IS THE MEAT?
LOMO IS RIB EYE.
I'M GONNA START CUTTING IT
INTO SLICES,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
CUT IT IN STRIPS.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER, SALT,
GARLIC.
CREAMY, OKAY.
THAT'S CORRECT.
SOY SAUCE LAST.
AND YOU'RE GONNA GET IT READY
LIKE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN A FRYING PAN.
IS THIS A SPECIAL
KIND OF PAN?
THAT'S MADE IN PERU.
WOW, THAT IS
SOME THIN METAL.
SO THAT BABY
GETS HOT FAST.
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
LOOK HOW FAST
THAT GOT HOT.
YEP.
OKAY.
GONNA ADD THE OIL,
THE LOMO.
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO
IS WAIT TILL THE BOTTOM GETS
A LITTLE BIT COOKED BROWN.
PUT A LITTLE
CRUST ON IT.
YOU KNOW, YOU WANT IT
LIKE A BARBECUE.
THEN YOU FLIP IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD THE ONION.
NOW WE'RE COOKING.
SO SOME TOMATOES GO DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF VINEGAR.
AND THEN
A "POQUITA CERVEZITA."
EXACTLY.
WHATEVER THAT WAS.
WHAT WAS THAT?
BEER.
OH, A LITTLE BEER,
A LITTLE CERVEZA?
A LITTLE BEER.
I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY AT HOME
RIGHT NOW
WHOSE MOUTH IS NOT WATERING,
'CAUSE MINE IS.
A LITTLE SALT FOR THAT.
NOW THE LAST THING WE'RE WAITING
FOR, BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
IS FRENCH FRIES,
REGULAR OLD FRENCH FRIES.
SOAKED IN WATER
AND COOKED.
NOW WE'RE READY TO PUT IT
ON THE PLATE, OKAY?
HERE YOU GO.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF RICE.
COME ON, BABY.
WE ARE READY.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY.
NOW WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE PART
OF THE DISH?
THE BEEF.
OKAY.
MMM. MMM!
(speaking indistinctly)
YEAH?
MM-HMM. FANTASTIC.
OH, MY GOSH.
THE WAY THE PAN WAS SO HOT, YOU
BROKE THE TOMATO DOWN SO FAST,
SO IT WORKS INTO THE SAUCE,
BUT IT'S NOT A TOMATO SAUCE.
LOOK AT THAT.
I DON'T CARE IF YOU LIVE WITHIN
200 MILES. YOU SHOULD WALK HERE.
RIGHT ON POINT GOODNESS.
(man) LOMO SALTADO.
(woman) DELICIOUS.
IT WAS LIKE EATING HAMBURGER,
FRENCH FRIES AND GRILLED ONIONS
ALL IN ONE BITE.
HOW ARE WE DOING? OKAY?
VERY, VERY GOOD.
I DON'T THINK YOU COULD GET
BETTER PERUVIAN FOOD ANYWHERE.
ARROZ CON MARISCOS.
I AM FROM PERU. HERE IN CHICAGO,
WE ALL RECOMMEND THIS PLACE.
I'D DEFINITELY
COME BACK HERE.
THIS IS A FOOD TOWN.
THAT'S A GREAT COMPLIMENT.
THIS HAS BEEN
A REALLY MEMORABLE EXPERIENCE.
THANK YOU.
I AM VERY HAPPY FOR YOU,
VERY HAPPY FOR YOUR FAMILY.
I THINK YOUR MOM HAS GOT TO BE
THRILLED WHAT SHE SEES GOING ON.
UP NEXT...
THE FOOD IS WHY EVERYBODY COMES.
WE'RE HEADING TO OKLAHOMA...
SO TENDER,
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
TO SCHNITZEL-IZE.
WIENEL SCHNITZER.
WEENIE SCHNITZER.
IT'S WIENER SCHNITZEL.
THAT'S THE WAY
YOU GOT TO DO IT.
WHEN I WAS A KID GROWING UP
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
IN FERNDALE, ONE OF
MY FAVORITE PLACES TO HANG OUT
WAS THE FERNDALE BAKERY.
NAOMI AND SVEN
USED TO HOOK ME UP
WITH THE FRESH BAKED BREAD
AND THE PASTRIES.
IT'S ACTUALLY SURPRISING
I DIDN'T BECOME A BAKER.
SO ON TRIPLE "D"
WHEN I'M ROLLING THROUGH
A PLACE LIKE OKLAHOMA CITY,
WHERE I'M EXPECTING, YOU KNOW,
STEAK AND BARBECUE,
AND I HEAR ABOUT A GERMAN BAKERY
CALLED INGRID'S,
WHERE THEY'RE DOING FRESH RYE
BREAD AND OVER 150 OTHER ITEMS,
YOU KNOW I GOT TO STOP
AND CHECK IT OUT.
(man) WHEAT AND WHITE.
WHEN YOU WALK IN, AND YOU CAN
ACTUALLY SMELL BREAD.
THEIR COOKIES--TO DIE FOR.
PASTRIES, PERFECT.
I LOVE THE PIES.
I LOVE THE BREAD.
BLUEBERRY BAGEL,
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
AND THAT'S JUST HALF THE MENU.
MEATLOAF.
AUTHENTIC GERMAN FOOD.
WHETHER IT'S THE BRATWURST
OR THE SCHNITZEL...
SCHNITZEL IN THE WINDOW.
TOPFLIGHT EVERY TIME.
EVERYBODY ELSE SAYS,
"WHERE ARE WE GONNA GO EAT?"
WELL, LET'S GO TO INGRID'S.
BUT THEY MIGHT HAVE LOST IT
IF IT WEREN'T FOR LONG-TIME
CUSTOMER LEE BURRUS...
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
WHO JUMPED IN WHEN THE FORMER
OWNER DECIDED TO SHUT DOWN.
CALLED THE LANDLORD
AND BOUGHT IT.
EVEN REHIRED THE OLD STAFF...
(man) PUMPERNICKEL.
INCLUDING HEAD BAKER
GREG SPITLER.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT
BREADS DO YOU GUYS BAKE?
2 DOZEN, MAYBE 30.
YOU HEARD HIM, 30...
(Greg) HOT BREAD.
WITH NINE KINDS
OF RYE ALONE.
SO WE'RE MAKING
LIGHT RYE.
YES, WE ARE.
OKAY, SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN.
CLEAR FLOUR.
SO THERE'S MORE GLUTENS
IN THE CLEAR FLOUR...
YES.
THAN THERE IS
IN ALL-PURPOSE?
YES, THERE IS.
OKAY, THAT'S WHAT GIVES
THE TEXTURE AND THE CHEW.
YEAH.
AND THEN WE ADD
A LITTLE SALT.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
AND WE ADD YEAST.
DO NOT LET YOUR SALT
AND YOUR YEAST TOUCH.
SALT WILL KILL THE YEAST?
THAT IT WILL.
MM-HMM-HMM.
THIS IS THE ONE
WE DON'T MEASURE.
GROUND CARAWAY.
THAT IS YOUR PREDOMINANT
FLAVOR IN ALL YOUR RYE.
OH, IT SMELLS AWESOME.
WE'LL SIT IT
IN OUR MIXING BOWL,
THEN WE'LL ADD
OUR WATER AND OUR SOUR.
IT'S A YEAST MIXTURE THAT
HAS A FLAVOR COMPONENT TO IT--
IT'S A LIVE CULTURE.
IT'S A LIVE CULTURE, AND THAT'S
GONNA FORTIFY THE FLAVOR.
SO HOW LONG WILL THIS MIX
LIKE THIS?
11 MINUTES, AND THEN WE'LL ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
HELP GET IT OFF
THE BOTTOM?
THAT IT DOES.
SO YOU DON'T HAVE
TO MUSCLE IT OUT.
SO WHEN YOU'RE DONE
WITH IT, WE--
WALK IT OVER
TO THE WORKBENCH,
LET IT SIT THERE
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
OKAY.
YOU CAN FEEL THAT
IT'S READY TO GO.
SCALE IT.
NOW HOW GOOD ARE YOU
WITH YOUR MEASUREMENTS?
DEPENDS ON WHAT DAY
OF THE WEEK IT IS.
SURE MAKES THAT
LOOK EASY.
A LITTLE FLOUR.
AND WE COVER 'EM
WITH PLASTIC.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET
THAT DRY SKIN ON IT.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA LET
THESE PROOF FOR FIVE MINUTES.
THEN IT'S LOAF TIME.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'VE
DONE THAT BEFORE.
OH, ONCE OR TWICE.
OKAY, SO THESE ARE DONE.
DO WE PUT ANYTHING ON 'EM?
NO, THEY GO STRAIGHT
INTO THE PROOF BOX.
FOR TEN MORE MINUTES.
THEY COME OUT
OF THE PROOF BOX...
OKAY.
WE SPRAY THEM WITH
A LITTLE WATER, SCORE 'EM.
AND THEN
INTO THE 400-DEGREE OVEN.
AND THEN WE TURN THE STEAM ON
FOR ABOUT 30 SECONDS.
THAT'S WHAT GIVES IT
A NICE THICK CRUST
AND A NICE,
SOFT INTERIOR.
HOW LONG DO THEY REST
BEFORE WE CUT INTO THEM?
NOW THIS HAS BEEN COOLING
FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME.
MAN, IT'S GOT SOME TANG.
IT GETS YOU RIGHT
BACK THERE IN THE JOWL.
A HUGE AMOUNT OF CRUST.
LOOK AT THAT. YOU GOTTA TRY IT.
THE RYE BREAD IS
WONDERFUL.
DID YOU SAY
THIN OR REGULAR?
(Guy) MAKE A KILLER SANDWICH
WITH THIS.
ALL THEIR SANDWICHES
ARE JUST GOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
FROM LIVERWURST TO KNOCKWURST,
AND THIS FAVORITE...
THE REUBEN--BEYOND AMAZING.
AND AT THIS JOINT,
MANAGER MAGGIE MINER
IS BUILDING 'EM FROM SCRATCH.
REUBENS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE NOW?
SAUERKRAUT.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTè SOME BACON,
WE'LL ADD SOME ONIONS.
WE COOK THIS DOWN.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME OIL TO THE POT.
OKAY, SO THIS IS THE SAUERKRAUT.
YOU BUY THE 5-GALLON BUCKET.
WE RINSE UNTIL
THERE'S NO SAUER LEFT.
GET SOME CARAWAY
GOING IN THERE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF CARAWAY.
THE REST
OF OUR SAUERKRAUT...
MORE CARAWAY, OKAY.
SUGAR,
BACON AND THE ONIONS.
APPLESAUCE, GIVES IT A LITTLE
BIT OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
APPLESAUCE GOES IN SAUERKRAUT.
NEW ON TRIPLE "D."
AND OUR BAY LEAVES, WATER.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
HOW LONG IS THAT GONNA SIT THERE
AND SIMMER-STEAM-COOK?
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
IT'S A VERY MILD SAUERKRAUT.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THIS HAS A NICE PALATE.
WHAT'S THIS GOING?
WE MAKE IT
ON OUR REUBENS.
DO YOU HAVE A SPARE REUBEN,
UH, LAYING AROUND?
I THINK WE CAN PROBABLY
MAKE YOU ONE.
OKAY.
THIS IS ONE
OF THE LOAVES OF BREAD
YOU DID
IN THE BAKERY TODAY.
OUR THOUSAND ISLAND
THAT WE MAKE, SWISS CHEESE.
GET THIS GRILL
GOIN' HERE.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA GRILL UP THAT BREAD.
THIS IS OUR CORNED BEEF.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR SAUERKRAUT.
NOTHIN' WRONG WITH THAT.
IT'S HOT.
AND THAT'S OUR REUBEN.
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
MMM.
OKAY?
DELICIOUS.
GOOD.
GREAT FLAVOR. THE SAUERKRAUT
PLAYS RIGHT INTO IT.
MMM, THE BREAD IS GANGSTER.
YOU WANT TO TRY THIS?
CAN'T GET PAST
THE REUBEN.
OUTSTANDING, VERY TASTY.
THE FOOD'S ALWAYS GOOD.
'CAUSE LEE'S KEPT IT GOIN'...
31 YEARS IN BUSINESS.
THE WAY IT'S ALWAYS BEEN.
I LOVE THE FOOD.
THERE'S JUST THAT MADE-
FROM-SCRATCH, HOMEMADE FLAVOR.
I'M HAVING THE SAUERBRATEN.
WONDERFUL.
BRATWURST PLATE.
GET IT EVERY TIME I COME.
AND THIS GERMAN CLASSIC...
SCHNITZEL UP.
IT'S A WIENEL SCHNITZER.
WEENIE SCHNITZER.
IT'S WEINER SCHNITZEL.
DELICIOUS.
SO HOW DO WE
START THIS OFF?
FIRST OF ALL,
WE USE OUR OWN BREADCRUMBS.
NORMALLY WE JUST USE
THE MILD RYES.
YOU DRY THE BREAD OUT.
AND WE GROUND THEM DOWN
TO WHERE THEY'RE REAL FINE,
AND WE ADD GRANULATED GARLIC,
PEPPER AND SEASONED SALT.
NOW WE BUST OUT EGGS.
AND CRACK 'EM UP.
YOU'RE CRACKIN' ME UP.
AM I?
PUT SOME MILK IN THAT?
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA PUT
A CUP OF MILK IN THAT.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS UP.
NOW DO WE HAVE ANY FLOUR
GOING INTO THIS?
HOPEFULLY WE'VE DONE
OUR BREADCRUMBS FINE ENOUGH
THAT WE CAN SKIP THE FLOUR.
I LIKE THAT.
SO WE CUT OUR OWN PORK LOIN.
ABOUT A 2 1/2-OUNCE,
3-OUNCE SLICE.
THIS IS FOR OUR SMALL PORTION.
OH, YES, BECAUSE
I'M A PETITE EATER.
THEN WE TAKE OUR BAGGIE.
AND POUND IT OUT.
SO THEN WE'RE
GONNA SOAK THIS.
AND THEN INTO
THE BREADCRUMBS,
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA
COOK THIS IN?
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
ON THE FLATTOP.
A LITTLE PRESS, FLIP IT,
BOTH SIDES NICE GOLDEN BROWN.
YEP.
AND WHAT'S THIS
GONNA GET SERVED WITH?
SAUERKRAUT,
THE GERMAN POTATO SALAD...
WHICH IS HELD WARM.
RED CABBAGE
WE MAKE HERE.
HOW WE LOOKIN'?
IT LOOKS GREAT.
READY TO PULL IT?
YEP, WE ARE.
GOOD, AND THEN WE'LL HIT IT
WITH SCRATCH-MADE GRAVY.
YEP, BEEF STOCK, MAKE A ROUX,
MIX IT ALL UP,
AND THERE'S OUR GRAVY.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
MMM. THAT'S THE WAY
YOU GOTTA DO IT.
LOOK AT THAT. COOKED PERFECTLY,
NICE AND MOIST. MMM.
KIND OF BUTTERY
WITH THE GRAVY. I LIKE IT.
YOU'RE HUNGRY,
COME EAT THIS.
SCHNITZEL IN THE WINDOW.
SO TENDER.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
ALL THEIR FOOD
IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
GOT A COUPLE
OF SPECIALS.
BROTHER, YOU GOT
A FULL-TIME OPERATION.
YES, I DO.
IT'S ONE-OF-A-KIND,
THAT'S ALL I GOT TO SAY.
GREAT JOB, LEE. THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH. THANKS.
NEXT UP,
WE'RE HEADING EAST...
I JUST LOVE THE PLACE.
TO A PUB IN BUFFALO...
GOT THE HARP.
WHERE THE BEER...
BEER CHEDDAR SOUP!
IS IN THE BOWL.
WE ADD SOME IRISH BEER.
ALL THAT BEER?
ALL THAT BEER.
WOW, YOU CAN SMELL
THE BEER LIKE CRAZY.
I'M HERE ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF BUFFALO, NEW YORK,
AND IN A PREDOMINATELY
IRISH NEIGHBORHOOD,
WHERE WE'VE GOT A GREAT STORY
ABOUT TWO BROTHERS.
KEVIN, OR LYLES,
AS HE WAS KNOWN,
WAS PART OWNER
OF THIS NEIGHBORHOOD PUB
UNFORTUNATELY, IN 2002,
HE PASSED AWAY.
NOW NO ONE WANTED TO SEE
THE PUB LEAVE THE FAMILY,
SO HIS BROTHER PAT,
A LOCAL FIREMAN,
ALONG WITH HIS
BROTHER-IN-LAW, TOOK OVER.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE LOVE
ON TRIPLE "D" IS TRADITION.
TIME TO CHECK OUT
BLACKTHORN RESTAURANT & PUB.
(man) STUFFED PEPPER
IN THE WINDOW.
CHICKEN WINGS.
SOUTH BUFFALO WINGS,
PERFECTLY DONE.
PLATING THAT STEAK.
VEGETABLES COMING DOWN.
IRISH BEER CHEDDAR.
THANK YOU.
BEER CHEDDAR SOUP--
FANTASTIC.
FRIED BOLOGNA, COMIN' UP.
IT'S TRADITIONAL
BUFFALO FOOD.
AT A TRADITIONAL
BUFFALO JOINT.
ALMOST THE EXACT SAME SINCE '77.
SO WHEN PAT LALLEY...
HOW'S EVERYTHING GOING?
AND HIS BROTHER-IN-LAW
LARRY ADYMY TOOK OVER
FOUR YEARS AGO...
GOT THE HARP.
THEY STUCK WITH TRADITION.
WE TWEAKED SOME THINGS, REDID
THE MENU, BUT THE CLASSICS
OF THE BLACKTHORN
HAVEN'T BEEN TOUCHED.
LIKE THIS LOCAL CLASSIC...
BEEF ON WECK.
ROAST BEEF
ON A SALT- AND CARAWAY-TOPPED
KIMMELWECK ROLL.
THIS IS WHAT
BUFFALO'S KNOWN FOR.
THE PERFECT SANDWICH.
AND HEAD CHEF
MAX LEATHERBARROW...
COMIN' UP!
IS CRANKING OUT AROUND
20,000 A YEAR.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR ROAST BEEF
FOR THE BEEF ON WECK
SANDWICH.
BEEF ON WECK.
WELL, SHOW ME
THE WAY WE DO IT.
START WITH ONIONS
IN THE PAN,
CARROT, CELERY.
SO WE'RE MAKING
A LITTLE MIREPOIX,
IT LOOKS LIKE,
TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS PAN?
BASICALLY, YES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE BEEF IN THE PAN--
ANGUS ROUND.
BIG TOP ROUND.
BIG TOP ROUND. NEXT,
I DO A BROWNING AGENT.
AGENT BROWNING.
LIKE A LITTLE KITCHEN BOUQUET
OR SOMETHING ALONG THAT--
YEAH, RUB THAT IN.
ALL RIGHT,
WE PUT A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE
ON, MONTREAL STEAK SEASONING.
PAT THAT DOWN, AND THEN LAST,
WE HAVE SOME FRESH ROSEMARY.
THAT YOU GROW
IN YOUR BACKYARD.
YEAH, I BROUGHT
THIS FROM HOME.
SO WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN NOW?
THIS IS GONNA GO
STRAIGHT IN THE OVEN.
300 DEGREES, 3 HOURS.
ARE YOU GOING FOR
AN INTERNAL TEMPERATURE?
YEAH, I'M LOOKING
FOR AROUND MAYBE 110.
SO YOU'RE REALLY
COMING OUT MEDIUM-RARE.
HE'S READY.
WOW.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
LOOK AT THAT BAD BOY.
SO YOU LET IT REST,
WHEN YOU SLICE IT ALL THE JUICES
DON'T COME FLOWIN' OUT.
EXACTLY.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE AU JUS FROM?
YEAH, I BASICALLY
PUT ALL THE VEGETABLES
AND PAN DRIPPINGS INTO A POT,
ADD WATER, KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE BROWNING AGENT,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER, BEEF BASE.
ONCE THE AU JUS COMES TO A BOIL,
WE STRAIN IT,
AND THAT'S YOUR AU JUS.
THAT'S IT,
THEN WE'LL SLICE IT.
THIS IS OUR
FINAL PRODUCT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT THIS ON WECK.
START WITH THE BUN,
DIP THE TOP IN AU JUS,
INTO OUR CARAWAY SEED
AND KOSHER SALT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN SOMEONE
DO IT HERE IN LOCATION.
I'VE ALWAYS SEEN IT COME
WITH IT ON THERE.
WHY NOT FRESH?
WHY NOT?
ALL RIGHT, TAKE OUR BEEF,
ADD A DIP RIGHT IN THE AU JUS.
LET IT WARM UP FOR A MINUTE,
WE GOT THE BOTTOM OF OUR BUN,
PUT OUR BEEF ON THERE, TOP
OF THE BUN--THERE YOU HAVE IT.
SO THAT'S IT--BEEF ON WECK.
NICE AND SOAKIN'...
WECK.
MMM. WOW. THAT IS SO TENDER.
BIG FLAVOR.
CRAZY WITH THE SALT
AND THE CARAWAY.
THAT AU JUS
IS AWESOME, TOO. MMM.
I COULD ONLY PROBABLY EAT ABOUT
1,000 OF THOSE. NICE JOB, MAN.
BEEF ON WECK
IS SO DELICIOUS.
MEAT'S PERFECT. IT'S TENDER.
THERE'S NO GRISTLE, NO NOTHING.
NO SNIZZLE ON THE GRISTLE?
NO SNIZZLE ON THE GRISTLE.
THAT'S HOW THEY SAY IT
AROUND HERE.
BEEF ON WECK
IN THE WINDOW!
I JUST LOVE THE PLACE.
YOU'RE MY CHICKEN WINGS
WITH RANCH, RIGHT?
THIS IS OUR TABLE, ACTUALLY.
AND THIS IS WHERE PAT'S
FIREHOUSE BROTHERS LIKE TO SIT.
EVERYONE COMES HERE.
THEY KNOW IT'S GOOD FOOD.
COPS AND FIREMEN ALWAYS KNOW
THE BEST PLACES TO EAT.
AND WHAT TO EAT.
BEER CHEDDAR SOUP.
A NICE LITTLE KICK TO IT,
VERY GOOD.
AND IT'S MORE-THAN-30-YEAR-OLD
BLACKTHORN RECIPE.
I SEE CHEESE AND BEER.
WE'RE MAKING SOME SOUP.
WE'RE MAKING SOUP.
THIS IS OUR IRISH BEER
CHEDDAR AND POTATO SOUP.
OKAY.
START OUT WITH BUTTER,
SPANISH ONION. GIVE THAT A STIR.
I'M GONNA
LET THESE SWEAT.
AND WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN NOW?
WE ADD SOME IRISH BEER.
ALL THAT BEER?
ALL THAT BEER.
WOW. THAT'S
A TON OF BEER, DUDE.
I MEAN, I'VE HAD A LOT
OF CHEDDAR BEER SOUP BEFORE,
BUT I DON'T THINK
I'VE EVER SEEN THAT AMOUNT.
LET THIS
COME TO A SIMMER.
TAKES ABOUT
10, 15 MINUTES.
GONNA ADD OUR POTATOES.
THIS MIGHT SPLASH.
NOW THESE ARE PEELED
AND PARBOILED.
YES.
HOW MUCH OF THIS SOUP
DO YOU GUYS GO THROUGH A WEEK?
ABOUT 20 GALLONS A WEEK.
SO POTATOES ARE IN.
WE ADD OUR SEASONINGS,
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER,
MONTREAL STEAK--
MONTREAL SEASONING, OF COURSE.
McCORMICKS LOVES YOU.
SEASONED SALT, CHICKEN BASE.
STIR THAT IN.
BRING THIS UP TO A BOIL.
LOOKS GREAT SO FAR.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE
GONNA ADD THE CHEESE
ABOUT A HANDFUL
AT A TIME--
SHREDDED CHEDDAR
AND MONTEREY JACK.
AND JUST SLOWLY WHISK
THAT CHEESE IN.
YEAH. IF WE DO IT ALL AT ONCE,
OBVIOUSLY, IT'S GONNA CLUMP UP.
CLUMP UP, AND YOU'LL HAVE
THE BOTTOM OF SOMEBODY'S FONDUE.
EXACTLY.
THE CHEESE IS IN.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
FINAL STEP, HEAVY CREAM, AND WE
ADD A LITTLE NACHO CHEESE SAUCE
JUST FOR COLOR AND TO--
THICKEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
SURE.
SO LET THAT SIMMER. AND THEN
WHAT DO WE SERVE IT WITH?
SIDE OF SALTINE CRACKERS. THERE
YOU GO. HOT SAUCE, IF YOU WISH.
WOW, YOU CAN SMELL THE BEER
LIKE CRAZY.
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S BIG, DEEP,
RICH FLAVOR, CREAMY.
JUST HAD, LIKE,
A PERFUME OF THE BEER.
MMM. THAT IS THE MOST BEER I'VE
EVER SEEN IN BEER CHEDDAR SOUP.
WE DON'T MESS AROUND WITH BEER
IN BUFFALO.
NO, YOU DON'T.
WHAT KIND OF SAUCE
IS THAT?
THAT'S WING SAUCE.
MMM, OH, OH, OH. WITH THE HOT
SAUCE IN THERE, REALLY GOOD.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANKS.
REALLY GOOD JOB.
FANTASTIC.
REALLY CREAMY
AND CHEDDARY.
(man) CHEDDAR SOUP
GOING UP.
ANYWAY YOU CAN PUT BEER IN
A SOUP, I THINK IT TASTES YUMMY.
(woman)
IRISH BEER CHEDDAR.
YOU CAN GET ANYTHING YOU WANT
HERE, AND YOU'D BE HAPPY.
ALL THE BUFFALO FAVORITES
YOU'D EXPECT...
CHICKEN WINGS.
NICE AND PLUMP
AND CRISPY.
AND A FEW THINGS YOU WOULDN'T.
CRAB CAKES.
DONE BALTIMORE STYLE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO TO
MARYLAND. THEY'RE RIGHT HERE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
THE BEEF ON WECK.
AT THE BLACKTHORN RESTAURANT
& PUB IN BUFFALO, NEW YORK...
HI, GUYS, HOW ARE YA?
OWNERS PAT LALLEY
AND LARRY ADYMY...
HERE YOU GO.
ARE PROUD TO BE SERVING UP
ALL THE LOCAL CLASSICS...
CHICKEN WINGS.
LIKE BEEF ON WECK.
PILED NICE AND HIGH.
BUFFALO WINGS...
THEY'RE NICE
AND PLUMP AND CRISPY.
AND A WHOLE LOT MORE.
CRAB CAKES ARE DELICIOUS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO TO
MARYLAND. THEY'RE RIGHT HERE.
WELL, GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN, MAN.
I'M A CRAB CAKE AFICIONADO.
START BY RUNNING OUR VEG
THROUGH THE FOOD PROCESSOR--
GREEN AND RED BELL PEPPER,
SPANISH ONION, CELERY.
LET IT SPIN.
I MIX IT TOGETHER,
JUST SO IT DOESN'T BREAK DOWN
REALLY BAD.
HOW MANY CLICKY CLICKY
CLICK-CLICK-CLICK?
BETWEEN 12 AND 15,
I GUESS.
YES, VERY NICE.
THAT GOES IN A BOWL. NEXT, WE'RE
GONNA ADD OUR CRABMEAT, EGGS.
SIX EGGS.
A LITTLE BIT OF DILL.
WHOA.
TAKE IT EASY ON THAT.
THRILLA WITH THE DILLA. WOW.
OLD BAY SEASONING,
GREEK DRESSING,
OUR LEMON DILL MAYO
THAT WE MAKE HERE.
TO DILL-IFY IT
ONE MORE TIME.
SURE.
AND WHAT WAS IN THIS?
LEMON JUICE,
DILL, MAYONNAISE.
OH, SURE. IT'S LEMON JUICE,
DILL AND MAYONNAISE.
IT'S A LEMON DILL MAYO.
HOW ABOUT--
CALL IT LEMON DILL MAYO.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD IDEA.
WE HAVE SOME CHOPPED GARLIC.
WHOLE MESS OF THAT.
PARMESAN CHEESE.
SWISS CHEESE.
OKAY.
PROVOLONE CHEESE,
MIX OF SHREDDED CHEDDAR
AND MONTEREY JACK.
IN THE CRAB CAKE.
IN THE CRAB CAKE
AND THEN 4 CUPS OF BREADCRUMBS.
WELL, THE ONLY THING
WE HAVEN'T STUCK IN THERE
IS THE KITCHEN SINK
AND YOUR HAT.
THAT'S NEXT.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP. NOW WE'RE
JUST GONNA PATTY THESE UP,
LOOKING FOR
ABOUT 5 1/2, 6 OUNCES.
THERE'S ONE OF OUR PATTIES.
FLOUR THIS.
PUT A NICE CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE.
NO SEASONING IN THE FLOUR?
JUST STRAIGHT-UP ALL-PURPOSE.
HERE'S OUR SECOND ONE.
FLOUR THIS UP.
AND HOW ARE WE
GONNA COOK THESE?
ON THE FLATTOP.
OUR BUTTER DOWN.
(whistles)
IT'S GONNA BE HOT.
SO A COUPLE MINUTES
EACH SIDE?
YEAH. WE'RE BASICALLY TRYING
TO GET A NICE CRUST ON 'EM,
HEAT 'EM THROUGH.
THAT'S A NORMAL ORDER?
YES.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S SERVE 'EM UP.
THESE GET SERVED
WITH RICE, VEGETABLES
AND WITH OUR LEMON DILL
MAYONNAISE. THERE YOU HAVE IT.
WE'LL JUST TRY IT WITHOUT
THE MAYO. LOOK IN THERE.
YOU SEE CRAB RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
THAT'S A GOOD SIGN.
MMM, GREAT FLAVOR,
GOOD MIXTURE OF CRAB.
I LIKE THE CRUNCHY VEGGIES
IN THERE.
THE DILL LEMON MAYO
COULDN'T BE ANY BETTER.
AND THE THING THAT IS THE BEST
IS THAT TEXTURE.
LOOK AT THAT CRUNCH ON THAT
RIGHT THERE. IT'S A GOOD CAKE.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANKS.
THE MARYLAND
CRAB CAKES--PERFECT.
CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE AND NICE
AND MOIST ON THE INSIDE.
THE DILL SAUCE
REALLY COMPLEMENTS IT WELL.
YOU HAD A BEER CHEDDAR
AS WELL, RIGHT?
BLACKTHORN'S IS
THE PLACE TO BE.
IT'S A GREAT NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT.
IT REALLY IS.
HE'S A GOOD GUY.
GREAT SERVICE, GREAT PEOPLE.
BEEF OF WECK.
I LOVE TO SEE THAT YOU GUYS
ARE HERE, YOU'RE DOING IT.
YOU DEFINITELY HAVE A PRESENCE.
YOU'RE TAKING CARE
OF YOUR COMMUNITY.
I THINK THAT'S AWESOME.
THANKS FOR COMING.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
OH, WE'VE HAD A BLAST.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OOPS.