HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MMM.
PIZZA, PORK AND PAPRIKASH...
CHICKEN PAPRIKASH.
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
(man) ORDER UP.
OFF THE CHARTS.
A BASIC JOINT...
I CALL IT
"FINE DINER-ING."
BUT GET THIS...
RAINDROPS
IN FLAVOR TOWN, BABY.
THEY'RE DROPPING DUCK CONFIT
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
OH, MY GOSH.
AND THE FRESH PORK...
CARNE ADOVADA.
IS SMOKED, ROASTED AND SAUCED
FROM SCRATCH.
LOOK AT THE COLOR.
MMM!
IN CLEVELAND...
HERE COMES YOUR FOOD.
THE LOCAL FAVORITE...
AND HERE WE'VE GOT
THE CHICKEN.
WHERE THEY'RE PILING ON...
JA.
THE OLD COUNTRY COMFORT FOOD.
WELL?
I'M NOT SUPPOSED TO TALK
WITH MY MOUTH FULL.
THAT'S TRUE.
YOU LISTENED TO YOUR MOTHER.
AND IN WESTERN NEW YORK...
I WISH I COULD EAT HERE
EVERY DAY.
THE FAMILY PIZZERIA...
THE PORTIONS
ARE HUMONGOUS.
WHERE THEY'RE MAKING PIES...
IT'S OUTRAGEOUSLY GOOD.
OUT OF SANDWICHES.
LARGE BEEF ON WECK.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S BEEF ON WECK
GONE WILD.
MMM. REALLY NICE.
GOOD JOB.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN SAN FRAN,
A CITY THAT IS KNOWN
FOR SO MANY THINGS,
BUT DID YOU KNOW
THAT THEY HAVE DISTRICTS HERE?
KINDA LIKE THE MARINA DISTRICT.
WELL, THEN THEY HAVE NORTH BEACH
AND THE SoMa DISTRICT.
AND, WELL, RIGHT NOW
I'M IN THE RICHMOND DISTRICT--
KIND OF LIKE THE FAMILY AREA,
I'M TOLD--
TO VISIT A RESTAURANT
THAT IS DOING REALLY WELL
EVEN THOUGH THEY'VE GOT
45 RESTAURANTS SURROUNDING THEM
IN A 4-BLOCK AREA.
IT'S CALLED Q,
AND THEY LIKE TO SAY THAT
THEY'RE FUNKY AMERICAN COMFORT--
MY KIND OF JOINT.
ORDER UP.
GRILLED VEGGIE APPETIZER.
I CALL IT
"FINE DINER-ING."
DUCK CONFIT
AT A PLACE THAT'S
AS COMFORTABLE AS Q, FANTASTIC.
OKAY, I GOT
YOUR SPECIAL MUSSELS.
MUSSELS, SALMON SANDWICH.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING, BROTHER?
PULLED PORK.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
MAC 'N' CHEESE.
IT'S AN OLD FAVORITE
WITH A LITTLE NEW KICK TO IT.
AND IT'S SERVED
WITH TATER TOTS.
IT'S ECLECTIC FUNK!
A GOOD FIT
FOR ANDREW GILLEN...
♪ LET'S SAIL THIS THING
AROUND ♪
WHO EARNED HIS CHOPS
COOKING BACKSTAGE FOR BANDS
LIKE P-FUNK
AND THE GRATEFUL DEAD.
WE GOT A DUCK.
11 YEARS AGO,
HE DECIDED
TO GO OUT ON HIS OWN...
ORDER UP.
AND OPEN THIS JOINT
WITH HIS WIFE BRYNN.
"FUNKY AMERICAN COMFORT."
YOU THINK?
HOW ABOUT DUCK CONFIT
FINISHED IN THE DEEP FRYER?
IT COMES OVER, LIKE,
A POLENTA IN A BEAUTIFUL SAUCE.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
OKAY, WE'RE DOING THE FUNKY,
AMERICAN-STYLE CONFIT.
FIRST, WE'LL MIX TOGETHER
OUR SPICES.
WE'LL GRAB SALT...
SOME OF THE MOJO MIX.
YOU ADD VARIOUS SPICES. GOT IT.
ALLSPICE,
WE GOT SOME GINGER.
WE HAVE SOME CLOVES HERE,
CHILI FLAKES, GROUND DOWN.
I ALMOST FORGOT
ABOUT THE BROWN SUGAR.
I NEVER WOULD LET YOU
HAVE DONE THAT.
SO I'LL MIX
THESE GUYS UP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
TAKE THESE DUCKS,
AND WE'RE GONNA
GIVE 'EM SOME LOVE.
SO EACH ONE OF 'EM GETS
LOVING, TENDER RUBBING?
EACH ONE GETS LOVING.
WOW. THEN WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN?
WE'RE GONNA WRAP 'EM, PUT
ANOTHER SHEET PAN ON TOP OF 'EM
AND TAKE 'EM
TO THE WALK-IN.
I TRY TO PUT
ABOUT 50 POUNDS ON 'EM.
AND JUST SIT THERE
AND PRESS THESE BAD BOYS
FOR HOW LONG?
48 HOURS.
AFTER THAT, YOU BRING 'EM OUT.
AND YOU GOTTA RUB OFF THE WATER
THAT'S SEEPED OUT OF 'EM.
PUT 'EM ON THE RACK.
AND NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
GOT SOME
RENDERED DUCK FAT HERE.
LOOK AT THIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SEAL IT UP,
'CAUSE IT'S GOTTA DO TIME.
YEAH.
AND WE ACTUALLY
COOK IT AT 350.
350 FOR HOW LONG?
3 1/2 TO 4 HOURS. WHEN IT'S
DONE, YOU COOL IT DOWN.
AND THEN YOU PUT IT INTO
THE WALK-IN FOR TWO WEEKS.
AFTER TWO WEEKS,
WE BRING 'EM OUT,
AND THEN TRY TO GET
AS MUCH GREASE OFF AS YOU CAN.
RAINDROPS
IN FLAVOR TOWN, BABY.
WE'LL PUT IT
IN A DEEP FRYER FOR A MINUTE.
AND WHAT'S THE SAUCE?
WE SAUTé SOME SHALLOTS
IN BUTTER,
AND THEN WE ADD...
CHERRIES TO IT.
IT'S GOT
SOME SWEETNESS TO IT.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE A CROSS BETWEEN
A MONTMORENCY AND A MORELLO.
AND THEN WE ADD
OUR SPICES TO IT--
SALT, A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
WHITE PEPPER,
WE'VE GOT ALLSPICE, CLOVES,
SOME SUGAR THAT WE PUT IN THERE
MOJO MIX,
SOME GROUND CHILI FLAKES.
NOW WE ADD OUR PINOT NOIR--
GET THAT GOING--
CRANBERRY JUICE,
RED WINE VINEGAR, SOY SAUCE.
SO I COOK THIS DOWN
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
AND THAT'S
WHAT MAKES THE RED SAUCE.
AND THEN THE OTHER SAUCE
THAT YOU PUT IN?
WE HAVE OUR CHICKEN STOCK.
WHEN THE DUCK'S DONE,
WE'LL PULL IT OUT.
AND THEN WE PUT 'EM
INTO THE SAUCE, SKIN SIDE UP.
RIGHT.
AND THROW THAT IN THE OVEN.
RIGHT UP ON TOP,
THREE OR FOUR MINUTES,
CRISP THAT SKIN
A LITTLE BIT.
WE'LL HAVE IT
HEAT THROUGH TO THE BONE.
SET THE REST
OF THE PLATE UP--
SOME POLENTA,
SOME GRILLED ASPARAGUS.
THEN WE TAKE IT OUT.
BEAUTIFUL.
THIS IS THE LOVE TOWN.
THEN WE FINISH IT
WITH A LITTLE GOAT CHEESE.
IT'S ONLY TAKEN 16 DAYS
TO MAKE THIS DUCK.
OH, MY GOSH.
DUDE, THAT'S BETTER
THAN DUCK CONFIT.
THIS HAS GREAT SEASONING.
THIS HAS DEPTH OF FLAVOR.
THE SAUCE
IS SWEET AND SAVORY.
THE CHEESE REALLY GOES WELL
WITH THE POLENTA.
IT'S RIDICULOUSLY LONG
TO DO THIS.
IT IS SO WORTH IT.
WE'VE WORKED ON THAT
FOR A WHILE.
MMM. GREAT JOB, BROTHER.
THANKS.
REALLY.
DUCK CONFIT.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
IT FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
THE POLENTA
ADDS A NICE FLAVOR.
OFF THE CHARTS.
THESE ARE ALL MY RECIPES.
I MADE ALL THOSE IN
THE FIRST FEW YEARS I WAS HERE.
THINGS THAT YOU WOULDN'T
NORMALLY FIND IN A DINER.
(woman) OKAY, THE MUSSELS.
REALLY TENDER.
GRILLED SALMON ON TOP
OF A SALAD--REALLY GREAT.
AND THIS FAVORITE...
A SPECIAL PORK CARNE ADOVADA.
IT'S A SLOW-ROASTED PORK.
STARTED AS A SPECIAL,
BUT THE LOCALS
WENT NUTS FOR IT.
OH, THE PULLED PORK.
DELICIOUS.
NOW IT'S ON THE MENU
EVERY DAY.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
HOW WE GONNA PLAY BALL?
THIS IS ROASTED GARLIC OIL
THAT WE MAKE, GARLIC.
AND THEN I'M GONNA START
PUTTING IN SOME CHILIES.
SO YOU'VE ALREADY ROASTED 'EM.
GET THEM IN THIS SAUTé.
MOJO MIX,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
THROW IN SOME WINE.
SO THAT'S A HALF A BOTTLE.
YEAH, I USE
A BOTTLE AND A HALF.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA THROW IN
SOME GOOD CHICKEN STOCK.
NOTHING LIKE
HOMEMADE CHICKEN STOCK.
THESE ARE
NEW MEXICO CHILIES.
SO I'LL PUT
A FEW EXTRAS IN THERE,
THROW IN SOME ROSEMARY.
THAT'S AN ECLECTIC MIX
WE HAVE GOING.
YEAH.
OKAY, HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO?
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PURéE IT?
YEAH.
TO BREAK DOWN THOSE SEEDS
AND THOSE SKINS.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S
SOME BLENDING, BROTHER.
OKAY. NICE BIG PORK LEG.
SO WHAT'S THE RUNDOWN?
FIRST, I'M GONNA POKE IT.
PIERCE THAT FAT
IF WE WANT TO GET
ANY OF THIS FLAVOR
DOWN IN IT, RIGHT?
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE CHILI ON,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA TRY
TO GET AS MUCH AS WE CAN
INTO ALL THESE
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE HOLES.
AND THAT'S WHAT
IT'S GONNA GET ROASTED IN?
YEAH.
MMM.
WE'RE GONNA COVER THIS UP
AND PUT IT IN WALK-IN
FOR TWO DAYS.
NOW IT'S GETTING READY
TO GO TO THE SMOKER.
SO THIS BAD BOY, WITH THAT KIND
OF FLAME, CAN GET HOT.
ON THE TOP SHELF SO IT GETS
AS MUCH SMOKE AS POSSIBLE.
AFTER IT DOES HALF AN HOUR
IN THE SMOKER,
PULL IT OUT,
THEN IT GOES INTO THE OVEN.
YEAH.
AND IT'S GONNA GO
IN THE OVEN HOW LONG?
THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
NOW IT'S READY.
LOOK AT THE COLOR ON THAT.
DARE ME.
ISN'T THAT COOL?
IT WASN'T THAT BIG OF A DARE.
I JUST WANTED TO EAT IT. MMM!
WE'RE JUST GONNA HEAT IT UP
WITH A LITTLE STOCK...
PORK STOCK.
THAT'S LIKE MY GATORADE.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAUCE.
THAT'S SOME GOOD LOVE
RIGHT THERE.
WHAT IS IT SERVED WITH?
GRILLED CORN, BLACK BEANS,
PAPAYA SALSA
AND A SIDE OF CORN TORTILLAS.
MMM. REALLY NICE.
IT'S GOT RICH FLAVOR.
MMM. THAT PORK OPENS UP
THE LONGER IT SITS
IN THAT SAUCE.
IT LOVES THE SAUCE.
IT DOES.
NOT TOO SPICY. YOU CAN
STILL TASTE THE PORK. MMM.
IT'S COMPLEMENTED
BY THE PEPPERS.
THE BEANS ARE TENDER.
THE CORN'S GOT GREAT SWEETNESS.
THE SALSA'S RIGHTEOUS.
REALLY GOOD. CONGRATS.
THANKS, MAN.
THE CARNE ADOVADA?
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE, BUT IT'S
GOT SOME SWEETNESS, TOO.
JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF SEASONINGS.
REALLY, REALLY NICE.
RIBS WITH HOT SAUCE.
IT COVERS ALL POINTS
FROM FLAVOR TO TEXTURE.
IT'S CONSISTENTLY WONDERFUL.
I LOVE THE Q.
GREAT JOB, MAN.
REALLY GREAT JOB. ENJOYED THIS.
THANKS.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING EAST
TO CLEVELAND...
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THIS FOOD TO PEOPLE?
CENTRAL EUROPEAN.
FOR OLD COUNTRY COOKIN'.
THAT'S SCHNITZEL 101.
LUCKY ME.
I SO DIG COMING TO CLEVELAND.
I GET TO SEE MY COUSINS
AND DYNAMITE LOCATIONS FOR
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHAT'S EVEN BETTER
IS WHEN YOUR COUSIN RECOMMENDS
A LOCATION YOU SHOULD VISIT
ON TRIPLE "D."
NOW, HEIDS,
IS THIS PLACE THE BOMB?
THIS PLACE
IS THE BOMB, GUY.
WAIT TILL YOU TRY THEIR
PAPRIKASH. IT IS UNBELIEVABLE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THEY CALL IT STERLE'S.
CHICKEN PAPRIKASH.
(woman) HERE WE'VE GOT
THE CHICKEN.
IT IS AWESOME.
AND WHEN COUSIN HEIDI TALKS,
I GOTTA PAY ATTENTION.
YOU CAN TELL
YOU'RE COOKING FROM SCRATCH.
VEAL GOULASH.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THIS FOOD TO PEOPLE?
CENTRAL EUROPEAN.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
WIENER SCHNITZEL.
THE ACCENT THAT I HEAR,
IS THAT, UH...
GERMAN.
OH, IT IS GERMAN. JA.
IT IS GERMAN.
AND GERMANY
IS WHERE MARGOT GLINSKI
FIRST LEARNED
THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
ONE...
MY GODMOTHER
HAD A RESTAURANT...
DIG IN!
AND I WAS
MAYBE 5, 6 YEARS OLD...
PASS IT ON.
AND I WAS PICKING UP
THE BEER BOTTLES,
AND I ALWAYS LIKED THAT.
DID YOU GUYS SHARE?
SHE CAME TO THE STATES
IN '66...
ENJOY IT.
AND 22 YEARS LATER,
SHE JUMPED AT THE CHANCE
TO RUN THIS LOCAL LANDMARK.
(woman)
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
(Margot) WE TOOK
THE STAFF ALONG,
AND THEY COOKED THE SAME WAY
FOR THE LAST 40 YEARS.
JA.
PAPRIKASH.
OKAY, THIS IS THE CHICKEN
FOR CHICKEN PAPRIKASH.
SOME SEASONED SALT, OKAY?
WHAT DOES "PAPRIKASH" MEAN?
SPICY GRAVY.
NOT HOT, HOT, BUT, YOU KNOW,
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF KICK.
SALT AND PEPPER...
SOME GARLIC POWDER.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
THEN YOU TOSS IT UP.
WE LET IT SIT OVERNIGHT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
COOK IT?
THEN WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT.
COOKING IT
IS MORE THE GENERAL TERM.
OKAY.
WE'LL DO IT YOUR WAY.
(giggles)
YOU PUT SOME FRESH ONIONS
ON THE SHEET,
AND THEN YOU LAY
YOUR CHICKEN DOWN.
AND IN THE OVEN IT GOES.
FOR 45 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE MAKING DUMPLINGS.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH INSTANT MASHED POTATOES.
INSTANT MASHED POTATOES?
YOU CAN DO WITH MASHED,
BUT, YOU KNOW, MASHED
ARE NOT CONSISTENT.
SOME POTATOES
HAVE TOO MUCH WATER.
THEN THE DUMPLINGS
COME OUT FUNNY.
WE ADD THE MARGARINE...
AND SALT.
SOME HOT MILK.
YOU WANT ME TO WHISK,
OR YOU GOT IT?
THAT WOULD BE NICE.
WE PUT SOME SOUR CREAM.
WE'VE GOT SOME EGGS.
I FEEL LIKE
THE MAD SCIENTIST HERE.
THAT'S JUST ABOUT
THE WAY IT IS, YEAH.
NOW WE DUMP SOME FLOUR HERE,
DUMP IT OUT.
YOU WANT TO KNEAD IT BY HAND.
THIS IS PRETTY CLOSE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
ROLL IT, YEAH.
SO LET ME SEE.
YEAH, NICE AND THIN.
CUT IT UP.
AND THEN YOU JUST GIVE 'EM
A LITTLE ROLLY-ROLL?
OH, YEAH.
WE SALT THE WATER AND THEN
THROW ALL OF THEM IN.
AND THEN WHEN THEY FLOAT,
THEY'RE READY?
YEAH.
WE GET 'EM OUT OF THERE,
PUT 'EM IN THE PAN.
SWEET BUTTER.
SO IT'S AN UNSALTED BUTTER?
YES.
BREADCRUMBS.
PUT SOME BREADCRUMBS ON 'EM.
HOW DOES IT LOOK?
IT LOOKS GREAT.
WE SHOVE THAT IN THE OVEN.
PAPRIKASH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PAPRIKASH GRAVY.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE ARE PUTTING IN
YOUR LARD, OF COURSE,
SAUTéED ONIONS,
GREEN PEPPERS...
TOMATO PASTE.
TOMATO PASTE. LET THAT
HANG OUT JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THEN WE'VE GOT SPANISH PAPRIKA,
PUT IN WATER,
ADD THE CHICKEN BASE,
SOME GARLIC,
SEASONED SALT, BEEF BASE,
WE'VE GOT BAY LEAF.
NOW COMES THE MY-RON.
THE WHAT?
WELL, I ALWAYS SCREW THAT UP--
MARJORAM OR WHATEVER.
WELL, I KNOW
WHAT I'M DOING.
"OR WHATEVER."
PEPPER.
AND TO GIVE IT A LITTLE HEAT,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
WELL, WE'LL LET IT COOK
FOR MAYBE ABOUT AN HOUR.
WE'RE GONNA THICKEN IT UP
WITH SOME FLOUR WITH SOME WATER.
THEN I ADD SOME SOUR CREAM.
WE LET IT COOK AND STRAIN IT.
STRAIN IT
AFTER WE THICKEN IT?
YES, BECAUSE YOU WANT
A NICE CLEAR SAUCE.
THEN THE CHICKEN COMES OUT
AND GOES INTO THE SAUCE, OKAY?
IT LOOKS GOOD.
IT IS GOOD.
GIVE YOU SOME DUMPLINGS.
THIS A NORMAL PORTION,
OR DO YOU JUST THINK I'M HUNGRY?
OUR PORTIONS
ARE ON THE BIG SIDE.
NOW, OF COURSE,
YOU WANT SOME GRAVY.
SO THAT'S IT? THAT'S
THE FAMOUS CHICKEN PAPRIKASH?
(whistles)
MMM. THAT IS GREAT.
CHICKEN'S REALLY TENDER.
SAUCE IS REALLY FLAVORFUL.
THE MOST UNIQUE PART ABOUT IT--
THE SOUR CREAM.
IT HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF A TANG TO IT.
YOU COULD GET USED TO IT.
GET USED TO IT?
I MIGHT BE MOVING IN, GIRL.
(woman) PAPRIKASH.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
AND THE CHICKEN
IS COMING ALL APART.
THE DUMPLINGS
ARE VERY GOOD.
IT REMINDS ME
OF MY GRANDMA'S PAPRIKASH.
REALLY?
(speaking indistinctly)
IT'S VERY ETHNIC.
YOU'RE IN THE OLD COUNTRY.
YOU HAVE A POLKA BAND
THAT PLAYS HERE.
OF COURSE.
EVERY SATURDAY.
(polka music playing)
WHEN YOU'RE DONE EATING,
YOU'VE GOT TO DANCE, YOU KNOW?
IT'S JUST SO FUN
AND FESTIVE.
THAT'S WHY
WE KEEP COMING BACK.
(woman) WE JUST HAVE
A WONDERFUL TIME
AND A WONDERFUL DINNER.
HERE WE GO.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
AND MADE THE SAME WAY
FOR 40 YEARS.
STUFFED CABBAGE.
FITZ'S VEAL GOULASH,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(man) MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
MMM, WOW.
AND MARGOT'S
CHILDHOOD FAVORITE...
WIENER SCHNITZEL.
JUST A BREADED VEAL CUTLET.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
LET'S MAKE WIENER SCHNITZEL.
YOU TAKE YOUR SCHNITZEL,
AND YOU BEAT IT UP.
OKAY.
YOU PUT A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
THEN WE PEPPER, TURN IT OVER.
BEAT IT SOME MORE.
DO YOU WANT TO TRY?
NO, I'M GOOD.
THEN YOU DRENCH IT IN THE FLOUR,
NICE AND GOOD, OKAY?
PUT IT IN THE EGG WASH.
ARE THESE YOUR BREADCRUMBS?
YEAH.
WE'VE GOT THESE BREADED UP.
WE'RE GONNA FRY 'EM.
YEAH, FRY 'EM.
THAT IS THE MOST UNCONVENTIONAL
FRYING PAN I HAVE--
LISTEN, WE ARE SAYING
WE ARE MODERN.
WE'RE JUST GOOD COOKS.
PUT THE SCHNITZEL IN.
THIS IS VEGETABLE OIL.
VEGETABLE OIL.
WAY TO GET HEALTHY ON ME.
THIS IS READY
FOR YOU TO EAT.
PUT SOME LEMON ON.
SO SQUEEZE THE LEMON?
SQUEEZE THE LEMON.
TWO PIECES
COME WITH AN ORDER?
YEAH.
WELL?
I MEAN, THE VEAL IS NICE,
LIGHTLY SEASONED.
THE LEMON IS DEFINITELY
THE WAY YOU HAVE TO GO WITH IT.
AND THE BREADING
IS HOLDING ON REAL NICE.
THAT'S SCHNITZEL 101.
LUCKY ME.
WIENER SCHNITZEL.
IT'S TASTY, TENDER.
IT'S CRISPY ON
THE OUTSIDE--EXCELLENT.
HERE COMES YOUR FOOD.
GOOD, WHOLESOME FOOD.
(playing polka music)
BETWEEN DANCING AND EATING,
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE
A GOOD TIME HERE.
THAT'S WUNDERVOLL.
THE BEST.
THERE'S NO QUESTION?
HANDS-DOWN, THIS IS--
NO QUESTION. HANDS-DOWN.
THIS IS THE GO-TO?
THIS IS THE GO-TO PLACE.
NOT SUPPOSED TO TALK
WITH MY MOUTH FULL.
THAT'S TRUE.
YOU LISTENED TO YOUR MOTHER...
ONCE.
I CAN'T WIN.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADING
TO WESTERN NEW YORK...
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
FOR PIES...
THE PORTIONS ARE HUMONGOUS.
PILED HIGH.
OH, LOOK--WE CAN FEED
A SMALL COUNTRY WITH ONE BITE.
SO HERE WE ARE--
NORTH TONAWANDA, NEW YORK,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF NIAGARA FALLS,
TO VISIT A PIZZA JOINT
THAT WAS OPENED IN 1972.
NOW THESE CATS,
WELL, THEY'RE SCRATCH-MAKING
THEIR PIZZA DOUGH
AND THEIR SAUCES.
THEY'RE MAKING JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS
THEY'RE MAKING
THAT'S REALLY UNIQUE
IS A WESTERN NEW YORK SPECIALTY.
MOST PLACES CALL IT
A BEEF ON WECK SANDWICH,
BUT NOT THESE GUYS, NOPE.
THIS IS A BEEF ON WECK PIZZA.
HERE WE ARE AT THE JUNCTION,
PIZZA JUNCTION.
(man) LARGE BEEF ON WECK.
BEEF ON WECK PIZZA.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE EATING
A SANDWICH, BUT IT'S A PIZZA.
THIS SANDWICH--ROAST BEEF
ON A SALT AND CARAWAY-TOPPED
KIMMELWECK ROLL--
TURNED INTO A PIZZA.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
A PIZZA JUNCTION ORIGINAL...
ALL RIGHT.
CRANKED OUT BY GENERAL MANAGER
RYAN FLECKENSTEIN,
WHO GREW UP IN THIS JOINT...
(woman) GO FOR IT.
AND JUMPED IN TO HELP
HIS PARENTS FOUR YEARS AGO.
GOT A LARGE
BEEF ON WECK COMING.
IT'S OUTRAGEOUSLY GOOD.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
YOU TAKE SOME BEEF BASE
AND ADD SOME GARLIC.
JUST MINCED GARLIC.
IT'S A REAL SIMPLE RUB.
YOU WANT TO MIX IT UP, GET
A NICE LITTLE PASTE LIKE THAT.
RUB IT ON THERE.
TOP ROUND.
YEP. JUST ADD SOME WATER,
FILL IT ABOUT HALFWAY.
PLASTIC-WRAP IT
THEN TIN FOIL.
AND TIN FOIL.
YEP.
SO YOU COMPLETELY LOCK IN
ALL THE MOISTURE.
EXACTLY.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
YOU'LL TAKE THIS
TO WHAT TEMPERATURE?
INTERNAL 120.
SO YOU GET
A NICE MEDIUM RARE.
A LITTLE STEAM KISS.
YEP.
SMELLS GREAT.
LET IT COOL, SLICE IT THIN.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
WHAT'S THE SAUCE
WE'RE PUTTING FOR THE PIZZA?
WE USE A HORSERADISH SAUCE
FOR IT.
(sighs) WITH A LITTLE
CREAMED HORSERADISH?
OH, YEAH.
OH.
YOU HAVE A LITTLE BUTTER.
SO WE'RE MAKING A ROUX--
BUTTER AND FLOUR.
IS THIS
MILK OR HEAVY CREAM?
IT'S GOOD OL' MILK.
THROW IN THE WHOLE GALLON.
SOON AS IT TIGHTENS UP,
THROW THE CARAWAY SEED IN.
THAT'S THE RYE BREAD FLAVOR
THAT WE LIKE, OR THE WECK.
KOSHER SALT.
AND SOME HORSERADISH.
WHOA! ALL OF IT?
YEP.
JUST GIVE ME A SOUP BOWL
OF THAT AND A CROUTON.
SO THAT'S READY TO GO.
NOW WE THROW A SKIN.
FLOUR, YEAST, SALT
AND SUGAR, WATER,
VEGETABLE SHORTENING.
(whistles)
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE CUT IT,
WEIGH IT AND ROLL IT OUT,
COVER IT, PUT IT IN A COOLER
FOR A 2-DAY RISE.
THAT'S A LOT OF DOUGH, MAN.
OH, YEAH.
WHAT SIZE DO WE MAKE
THOSE DOUGHS OUT AT?
1 POUND, 15 OUNCES.
ALMOST 2 POUNDS OF DOUGH.
CAN'T BELIEVE THAT YOU'VE
DONE THIS 90 OR 65 TIMES.
JUST TODAY.
SO YOU ROLL IT THROUGH SO IT
DOESN'T BUBBLE UP WHEN IT COOKS
'CAUSE YOU DON'T WANT IT
PUSHING ALL THE TOPPINGS OFF.
EXACTLY.
AND THERE'S OUR
HORSERADISH, CARAWAY SEED.
IT'S LIKE AN ALFREDO
THAT WE DID THERE WITH THE MILK.
NOW THE MOST IMPORTANT PART--
THE BEEF.
NICE SLOW, MOIST-COOKED--
THAT'S A LOT OF BEEF.
GO WITH SOME TOMATOES,
KEEP THAT BEEF NICE AND MOIST.
AND THEN NOT MOZZARELLA, HUH?
JACK AND CHEDDAR SHRED.
YEP.
AND FOR THE FINISHING TOUCH,
JUST A LITTLE BUTTER
AND SOME SALT AND CARAWAY.
DOING IT
IN THE TRUE WECK STYLE.
YEP.
HOW LONG DOES IT
GO DOWN FOR?
IT GOES IN
FOR ABOUT 12 TO 15 MINUTES.
AT 500 DEGREES?
YEP.
THERE WE GO. YEP.
NOW WE GOTTA DECK IT.
DECK IT?
WANT TO GET IT
OFF THIS PAN.
OH, I LIKE THIS IDEA.
SEE?
NICELY BROWNED UP NOW.
GOTTA HAVE THAT CRUST.
I WAS TOO WORRIED IT WAS GONNA
BE SOGGY UNDERNEATH THAT THING.
NOW FOR THE CUT.
(whistles)
MM-HMM, IT'S GREAT.
IT'S, LIKE, THE CHEESIEST
BEEF ON WECK I'VE EVER HAD
BUT WITH THE CRUNCHIEST ROLL,
BUN THING I'VE NEVER ENJOYED.
THE HORSERADISH SAUCE
IS NICE AND CREAMY.
THIS IS REALLY NICE.
GOOD JOB.
THANKS.
EXCELLENT. YOU CAN TASTE
THE CARAWAY SEEDS.
MMM.
AND YOU CAN TASTE THE SALT.
(Ryan) PIZZA GOING IN.
THE PIZZA'S ALWAYS GOOD.
LOADED SICILIAN.
THE PORTIONS
ARE HUMONGOUS.
NOW I WILL SAY YOU PUT
ABOUT 700 POUNDS MORE TOPPING
ON IT THAN ONE SHOULD.
OH, LOOK--WE CAN FEED
A SMALL COUNTRY WITH ONE BITE.
THAT'S A FAMILY TRADITION.
PIZZA'S COMING OUT.
PIZZAS HERE
HAVE BEEN HUGE FOREVER--
SINCE RYAN'S DAD...
OKAY.
AND MOM...
ANYTHING ELSE?
OPENED THE PLACE IN '72...
(man)
PEPPERONI IN THE WINDOW.
SERVING ALL KINDS OF PIES.
MMM.
THIS STANDS OUT
FROM EVERYBODY ELSE.
BUT THE SANDWICH THING...
I NEED MORE SAUERKRAUT.
IS A MORE RECENT DEVELOPMENT,
FROM THE BEEF ON WECK
TO A REUBEN.
MMM, THAT'S GOOD.
AND GET THIS--
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
AROUND HERE
THAT HAS
A PULLED PORK PIZZA.
WITH SCRATCH-MADE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
MMM.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT, TAKE A BIG OLD BUCKET
OF KETCHUP, BLACK PEPPER...
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
WHITE VINEGAR.
A LITTLE HONEY?
EXACTLY.
HOT SAUCE.
GOTTA HAVE THAT
IN BUFFALO.
RECONSTITUTED ORANGE.
(snorts)
'CAUSE YOU SEE
THAT EVERY DAY.
GIVES IT A GREAT FLAVOR.
OKAY, SO YOU MIX
THAT ALL TOGETHER,
POUR IT OVER THE TOP
OF THE PORK BUTT. (whistles)
PLASTIC WRAP.
THAT IS A TUB OF PORK.
THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
LONG-COOKING PORK--
6 HOURS, 300.
WE'RE NOT DOING
TRADITIONAL STYLE.
WE'RE JUST DOING IT
KINDA "PIZZA JOINT MAKES
PULLED PORK" STYLE.
YEAH.
(whistles) STRAINED OUT
ALL THE CHUNKS AND THE FAT.
AND THEN YOUR BARBECUE SAUCE
THAT WE COOKED THE PORK IN.
AND THEN YOUR
BUS-DRIVING METHOD.
I'VE DONE IT ONCE OR TWICE.
YEAH, IT'S NOT
YOUR FIRST RODEO.
PULLED PORK. LOOK AT THIS,
DUDE. THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
YOU'RE NOT DENYING IT?
NO, NOT AT ALL.
TOP IT OFF WITH THE CHEESE.
MOZZARELLA.
HOW LONG
WILL THAT GO DOWN FOR?
10, 12 MINUTES.
READY? DECK IT.
JUST TO GET THAT LITTLE
EXTRA CRUNCH ON THERE.
GOOD TECHNIQUE.
EXACTLY.
NICE CRUNCH TO THE CRUST
WITH SOME TENDER PORK.
NOT GREASY. RIGHT AMOUNT
OF SAUCE TO PORK RATIO.
BARBECUE SLIDER. PIZZA-LICIOUS.
DONE PIZZA'D IT.
(man) PULLED PORK.
TASTES JUST LIKE
A PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
YEAH, IT'S VERY GOOD.
THE SAUCE IS REALLY SWEET
AND BARBECUE-Y.
(Ryan) PIZZA GOING IN.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A GOOD PIZZA,
YOU COME TO PIZZA JUNCTION.
A BUFFALO PIZZA JOINT.
DOING
ALL THE BUFFALO FAVORITES--
BEEF ON WECK, WINGS...
IT'S SO GOOD.
AND THIS ONE...
STUFFED BANANA PEPPERS,
BUDDY.
IT'S A WESTERN NEW YORK STAPLE,
YEAH.
THAT FOLKS
CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF...
I CAN'T KEEP 'EM IN STOCK.
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
REUBEN PIZZA'S COMING OUT.
PIZZA JUNCTION'S BEEN
A SUBURBAN BUFFALO INSTITUTION
FOR 37 YEARS...
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
SERVING UP LOCAL FAVORITES
LIKE THAT
WESTERN NEW YORK SANDWICH
CALLED BEEF ON WECK
TURNED INTO A PIZZA...
MMM.
BUFFALO WINGS
AND ANOTHER BUFFALO CLASSIC--
STUFFED BANANA PEPPERS.
EVERYBODY'S GOT 'EM.
NOBODY DOES 'EM
AS GOOD AS US.
I LIKE THE ATTITUDE.
CAP 'EM AND CORE 'EM.
THE STEMS AND THE SEEDS
DON'T GO VERY FAR DOWN.
EXACTLY.
TAKE A LOOKY-LOO
AT THAT, OKAY?
DO A COUPLE OF THESE.
LOVE 'EM.
OKAY, NOW OIL 'EM UP
AND HIT 'EM IN THE OVEN
FOR A PRECOOK?
EXACTLY. 350 ABOUT 10, 12.
IT MAKES 'EM
A LITTLE MORE PLIABLE.
WE START STUFFING 'EM.
WITH OUR HOMEMADE STUFFING.
START OFF WITH OUR BUTTER,
SOME GARLIC FOR YOU,
MINCED WHITE ONIONS,
SOME BANANA PEPPERS.
WE TAKE THE ONES THAT ARE SMALL
THAT WE WOULDN'T STUFF, ANYWAY,
WE MINCE 'EM UP.
YOU GOTTA DO
SOMETHING WITH 'EM.
EXACTLY.
HOT CHERRY PEPPERS...
MMM.
SOME KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, HOT SAUCE.
HOT SAUCE PASTE, REALLY?
CAYENNE PEPPER
WITH SOME MORE HOT SAUCE TO IT.
JALAPEÑO JACK CHEESE?
YEP. ROMANO CHEESE.
OOH, OOH.
NOT ONE--TWO.
REALLY?
TWO. GOT SOME
ITALIAN SEASONED BREADCRUMBS.
WOW, MAN. GOOD OLD
ITALIAN SPECIALTY HERE.
SHOULD WE TASTE THAT?
VERY GOOD. I WILL.
MMM. WHY DO WE EVEN HAVE
TO STUFF THAT IN ANYTHING?
WHY CAN'T WE JUST GET
A COUPLE OF FORKS AND A 12-PACK?
SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
LET THIS COOL DOWN ENOUGH
THAT WE CAN TOUCH IT?
YEAH.
PEPPERS ARE COMING OUT
OF THE OVEN.
THEY COOL DOWN
JUST SO WE CAN TOUCH THEM.
LET'S SEE IT.
STUFF, STUFF, STUFF. WOW.
GOTTA MAKE SURE
IT GETS ALL THE WAY DOWN.
YES, YOU DO.
EVERYBODY LOVES THESE PEPPERS.
I CAN'T KEEP 'EM IN STOCK.
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
AS FAST AST YOU CAN MAKE 'EM,
PEOPLE ORDER 'EM.
YEAH.
SO YOU TAKE THESE, POP 'EM
IN THE OVEN, 350 DEGREES.
FIVE TO SEVEN MINUTES.
FIVE TO SEVEN.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THESE
ARE DONE, OF COURSE.
WELL, AT LEAST
THOSE WON'T BE HOT. (whistles)
PARM.
SOME TOMATO FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE DO A LOT OF TASTING
HERE ON TRIPLE "D."
I DON'T VERY OFTEN SEE
THE CHEF MAKE HIS OWN.
MMM. REALLY NICE JOB.
THAT'S A REALLY NICE PEPPER.
GREAT STUFFING INSIDE, MAN.
NOT TOO CHEESY.
YEAH, THERE IS A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT COMING IN THE BACK NOW.
NICE JOB, BUDDY.
THANKS.
IT'S GOT A REAL NICE KICK TO IT.
THE STUFFING MAKES IT.
I LOVE IT. MMM.
IT'S VERY SPICY.
(man) BURGERS UP.
THE FOOD IS OUTSTANDING.
ONION AND HALF PEPPERONI.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A GOOD PIZZA,
YOU COME TO PIZZA JUNCTION.
I WISH
I COULD EAT HERE EVERY DAY.
(woman) IT'S REALLY GOOD.
EVERY TIME I'M IN BUFFALO,
I COME TO PIZZA JUNCTION.
ONE OF THE THINGS I LIKE ABOUT
COMING TO THE BUFFALO AREA
IS ALL THE GIVING AND ALL
THE NICE THINGS THAT PEOPLE DO,
SO I JUST--I MEAN, I REALLY
WANT TO THANK YOU GUYS.
THIS HAS REALLY BEEN--
IT'S BEEN AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
ENJOY.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DO YOU WANT A BITE?
ARE YOU SHARING?
HUH?
IT WAS KIND OF
A LITTLE BITE, YEAH.
(laughing hysterically)