HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
TO THE OAKLAND COLISEUM
FOR A SPECIAL
TAILGATING EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES."
(Guy)
AND THIS TIME THE COOKS
ARE COMING TO US.
(woman)
WE'RE MAKING A MONSTER BURGER.
(Guy)
MOST PEOPLE ROLL OUT
TO DO TAILGATING,
YOU COME OUT WITH FRESH LINENS
AND A FRYER.
(Guy)
WE'RE CRANKING OUT
CHICKEN AND WAFFLES
AND TACKLING
A THAI NOODLE SALAD.
(Guy)
YOU KNOW WHAT REALLY IS
THE KICKER, THAT TOASTED RICE.
(Guy)
FROM A LITTLE JOINT
IN BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA.
WE'RE GOING DOUBLE COVERAGE...
THE CHAMPION HIMSELF,
THE SNAKE, KENNY STABLER.
(Guy)
ON THIS DOUBLE BURGER.
THE KICKER ON THIS...
THE CHILI'S THE KICKER.
(Guy)
FROM A NORTH CAL FAN FAVORITE...
WE'RE SCORING A STEAK SANDWICH
THAT'S MADE WITH WHAT?
(man)
JALAPENO PESTO.
THAT'S A FIRST.
PICTURE-PERFECT SANDWICH,
YOU'D LOVE THIS.
(Guy)
FROM A LOCAL LEGEND.
AND A SPECIAL VISIT WITH
A TEAM OF TAILGATE FANATICS...
THE BAD BOYS OF BBQ.
(Guy)
WHO'VE BEEN TAILGATING
THEIR WAY HERE SINCE 1995.
SALMON, PRIME RIB,
PULLED PORK, BABY BACK RIBS,
CHICKEN THIGHS, SKIRT STEAK.
DUDE, NICE JOB.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW AS "TRIPLE-D"
GOES TAILGATING.
♪
SO HERE WE ARE
ON MY STOMPING GROUNDS,
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
WHERE MY TEAM
THE OAKLAND RAIDERS
ARE GETTING READY
FOR A BIG GAME.
A LOT OF FOLKS
ENJOYING THE TAILGATING
OUT HERE IN THE PARKING LOT.
IT'S AS AMERICAN AS
"DINER'S, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES"
SO THIS TRIP WE THOUGHT
WE'D BRING 'EM BOTH TOGETHER.
WE CHECKED OUT SOME KILLER
"TRIPLE-D" LOCATIONS
IN THE GREATER OAKLAND AREA
AND INVITED SOME OF
THOSE RESTAURANTS TO
COME DOWN AND TAILGATE WITH US.
WE'RE GONNA START OUT
WITH A LITTLE JOINT
OUT OF BERKELEY
CALLED 900 GRAYSON
WHERE CHEF ERIC LARSON
IS CRANKING OUT
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE.
AND THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
I LIKE THE DIFFERENT FLAVORS
THAT THEY COMBINE HERE.
(Guy)
LIKE AHI TUNA
WITH A PICKLED GINGER
AND CARROT SLAW.
A PULLED-PORK SANDWICH...
THIS IS ONE OF THE BEST
IN THE BAY AREA.
(Guy)
OR AN ASIAN SALAD.
THIS IS A LADY BOY,
IT'S GOT LIME, MANGO,
GRILLED SHRIMP.
VERY GOOD.
SO NOW IT'S MEET THE CHEF.
RICK LARSON,
WHAT IS UP MY BROTHER?
NOT MUCH MY FRIEND.
SO MOST PEOPLE ROLL OUT
TO DO TAILGATING,
YOU COME OUT WITH FRESH LINENS
AND A FRYER.
SO WHAT ARE YOU MAKING ME?
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU A LADY BOY
THAI NOODLE SALAD.
WE START OFF
BY MAKING THE DRESSING.
DISTILLED WHITE VINEGAR,
WE'VE GOT SUGAR.
PUT SOME GARLIC IN,
LET THIS ALL COME UP TO A BOIL.
A LITTLE SAMBAL OELEK.
NICE AND HOT.
AND I'M GONNA MAKE A MARINADE
FOR THE SHRIMP RIGHT NOW.
NORMALLY WHEN YOU COME TO
A TAILGATING EVENT
AND YOU SEE A BLENDER
BEING WHIPPED OUT
IT'S BECAUSE
SOMEONE'S MAKING MARGARITAS.
GRAPE SEED OIL,
SOME RED ONION.
A LITTLE LEMON GRASS,
SOME RED CURRY PASTE.
MORE SRIRACHA HOT SAUCE.
SUGAR AND FISH SAUCE.
LET THAT BLEND.
WE'LL GIVE IT A LITTLE TASTE.
WORKS FOR ME.
WHAT SIZE SHRIMP
ARE WE PUTTING THIS WITH?
OH, 16/20.
SO THOSE SIT IN THE MARINADE
ABOUT TWO HOURS.
NOW I'VE GOT WATER BOILING
AND I'M GONNA PUT IN SOME
RICE NOODLES
AND LET THOSE SIT
FOR FIVE MINUTES.
I'LL STRAIN 'EM, COOL 'EM OFF,
PUT 'EM IN A BOWL AND ADD MANGO,
ZUCCHINI, CARROT, CUCUMBER.
THEN TOSS AND WE'LL ADD
THE MINT LEAVES HERE.
WE'VE GOT A LITTLE BASIL.
CAN'T FORGET THE DRESSING.
GO, GO, GO, GO, GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME SHRIMP INTO IT?
CAST-IRON, MY FAVORITE.
WE'LL PUT IN
A LITTLE GRAPE SEED OIL.
EVERYBODY SAUTES
AT A RAIDER GAME.
SHRIMP LOOK GREAT.
YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE PEPPER.
YOU CAN GO AHEAD
AND TOSS THAT UP.
HOW'S THAT?
PERFECT.
SRIRACHA AIOLI,
RICE POWDER.
TOASTING UP SOME RICE
AND JUST PUT IT IN
A SPICE GRINDER.
CHILI OIL.
BASIL OIL.
AND NOW COME THE SHRIMP.
SOME LITTLE MICRO GREENS
AND THERE WE ARE.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN GET
THE RIGHT ANGLE ON THIS,
BUT SEE THE RAIDER GUY?
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT YOU'LL EVER
SEE THIS HERE AGAIN.
OH YEAH, AND CHOPSTICKS.
OKAY, YOU CAN BRING THAT RV IN.
THIS SALAD LOOKS GREAT, MAN.
THE BASIL OIL AND THE CHILI OIL
ARE RIGHT THERE,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT REALLY IS
THE KICKER FOR ME ON THAT,
THAT TOASTED RICE,
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
JUMP ON IN ON ONE OF
THOSE SHRIMP.
IT'S COOKED PERFECTLY,
YOU GET SOME SALTY HEAT.
LET'S SHARE THIS WITH SOME OF
OUR RAIDER BUDDIES.
MY RAIDER BROTHERS,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S GOT THAT KICK.
I LIKE HOW THE WAY THAT HEAT
KIND OF CREEPS UP A LITTLE BIT.
WHEN YOU'RE PUTTING
SHRIMP IN SOMETHING,
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
PERFECT FOR A RAIDER GAME.
(Guy)
YOU HEAR THAT A LOT
BACK AT 900 GRAYSON.
(woman)
WHAT MAKES THEM GOOD,
THEIR ABILITY TO DO BASIC THINGS
VERY WELL.
(Guy)
FROM SANDWICHES TO THEIR TAKE
ON THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC...
WHEN YOU WANT COMFORT FOOD
YOU GET THIS.
(Guy)
CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
IT'S A WAFFLE
WITH A FRIED CHICKEN BREAST
WITH GRAVY ON TOP.
(Guy)
AND THEY CALL IT...
DEMON LOVER.
THAT'S SAYS WAFFLE.
I'M GONNA START THE GRAVY.
HEAVING WHIPPING CREAM
AND I'M GONNA ADD ONION.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME GARLIC,
JUST WHOLE, AND A LITTLE
WONDER FLOUR.
SO WE'LL MAKE SOME ROUX.
A LITTLE BUTTER,
GET THAT MELTED DOWN,
SOME MORE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
HEAVY CREAM.
YOU WANT TO WHISK THAT UP
TO GET IT THICK.
SO NOW WE'LL TAKE THIS ROUX
AND ADDING IT TO WARM CREAM.
I'VE GOT A SPECIAL TOOL
FOR THAT,
AN EMERSION BLENDER.
YOU WANT TO KNOW HOW
TO GET RID OF GOPHERS?
SO YOU'RE TAKING CARE OF
THE GARLIC RIGHT NOW
AND THE ONIONS
THAT ARE IN THERE.
WE'VE GOT PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
THAT'S GOOD.
NOW WE'LL MAKE DEMON FLOUR.
SO ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
SOME CALIFORNIA CHILI POWDER,
SPANISH PAPRIKA, CAYENNE.
GOTTA HAVE SOME HEAT, RIGHT?
SALT, GARLIC POWDER,
AND ONION POWDER.
(Guy)
THIS IS DEMON FLOUR.
I'M GONNA PUT IT INTO
OUR DREDGING STATION.
NOW WE'LL POUND OUT
SOME CHICKEN BREASTS.
THE FUN HASN'T STARTED
UNTIL YOU'RE POUNDING OUT
SOME CHICKEN BREASTS AT
A RAIDER GAME.
I LIKE TO CUT THE CAP OFF
TO MAKE IT POUND EASIER.
THEN I'M GONNA CUT THIS IN HALF
SO YOU GET TWO PIECES.
A PLASTIC WRAP.
(Guy)
SO I'LL POUND THESE OUT
NOT TOO MUCH.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
WATCH YOUR BACK.
PEOPLE ARE GONNA SMELL
THAT FRIED CHICKEN
COMING UP.
PUT A LITTLE BUTTERMILK
INTO ONE OF THOSE CONTAINERS.
EGG WASH.
CHICKEN INTO THE BUTTERMILK,
SOME EGG WASH.
(Guy)
INTO THE DEMON FLOUR.
OKAY, SO INTO 350 DEGREE OIL.
(Guy)
AND THEN WHAT EVERYBODY
BRINGS OUT TO A RAIDER GAME
A WAFFLE MAKER.
(Guy)
MAN, THAT IS SOME
TIGHT WAFFLE BATTER.
CHICKEN'S DONE.
SO WE'RE JUST
WAITING ON THE WAFFLE.
THERE'S THE WAFFLE,
THERE'S THE CHICKEN.
PUT SOME GRAVY ON THAT.
SAY WHEN.
YOU COULD HAVE BEEN POURING
BY NOW.
(Guy)
A LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER,
NICE COLOR ON THAT.
MMM, THAT'S SAVORY.
YOU GET THE SALT
AND THE CRUNCH OF THE CHICKEN.
THEN YOU GET INTO THE WAFFLE,
"OKAY, THIS IS GONNA BE SWEET,"
BUT THEN YOU NAIL IT
WITH THAT GRAVY.
THAT IS A WHAM-BAM COMBO.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
TO THE RAIDER DUDES OVER THERE,
THEY'RE GONNA THROW
THAT WHOLE POKER GAME
ON THE FLOOR TO TRY THIS.
OKAY, GUYS,
I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA WANT
TWO PLATES, BUT LADIES FIRST.
BROTHER, I THINK YOU SHOULD
SHOVE THE WHOLE THING IN MYSELF.
TENDER, DELICIOUS.
(woman)
IT TASTED SO GOOD.
(Guy)
VEGETARIAN GRAVY,
HOW'S THAT MAKE YOU FEEL?
WHAT, REALLY?
I THINK THEY'RE HAPPY.
YOU GONNA EAT THAT?
C'MON NOW.
(Guy)
THANK YOU MAN, GREAT JOB.
ALL RIGHT, WHEN WE GET BACK
IT'S ONE OF THE ULTIMATE OF
TAILGATE FOODS, BURGERS.
WHAT'S YOUR PREFERRED
BURGER TEMP?
MEDIUM-RARE.
(woman)
SO WE'RE MAKING
A MONSTER BURGER.
(Ken Stabler)
MMM.
WELCOME BACK TO
"TRIPLE-D" GOES TAILGATING.
HERE WE ARE
IN OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA.
NOW IN JUST A MINUTE
WE'RE GONNA MEET A CHEF
THAT IS GOING BIG
ON A TAILGATING CLASSIC,
THE BURGER.
BUT BEFORE WE DO THAT
I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO SOMEBODY SPECIAL,
SOMEBODY THAT TOOK
THE RAIDERS BIG
IN SUPER BOWL XI,
THE CHAMPION HIMSELF,
THE SNAKE, KENNY STABLER.
HOW ARE YOU, SNAKE?
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
NOW SNAKE, IF I SAY BURGER
YOU SAY...
LET'S GO BIG BURGER.
BIG BURGER IT IS.
NOW WE GOTTA GO CHECK OUT
RUDY'S CAN'T FAIL CAFE.
HUGE.
TWO PATTIES,
DOUBLE BACON,
DOUBLE CHEESE.
(Guy)
OR A SERIOUS SINGLE.
HUGE SELECTION OF BURGERS.
(Guy)
TOPPED WITH
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING,
LIKE SCRATCH-MADE CHILI.
AND THE CHEF DOING ALL THAT
AT RUDY'S IS SARA MAGGIO.
YOU KNOW WHO THIS CAT IS, RIGHT?
OF COURSE.
THIS IS THE MAN.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE OF
ALL TAILGATING FOODS, SNAKE?
I'M A CHILI GUY.
WE'RE DOING A MONSTER
CHILI-CHEESE BURGER.
YOU WEAR PART OF IT, RIGHT?
YES, YOU DO.
(Guy)
COULD YOU EAT CHILI LIKE THIS
BEFORE YOU'D GO ONTO A GAME?
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOU GOT JOE GREEN
SQUEEZING ON YOU.
OKAY, LET'S GET STARTED ON THIS.
HOT PAN, A LITTLE CANOLA OIL,
GARLIC, WHITE ONIONS,
RED BELL PEPPERS,
GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT IS?
SOME TYPE OF PEPPER.
JALAPENO.
JALAPENO, SPICY CHILI.
CAN YOU SEE IN THERE?
HARDLY.
I'M GONNA TRY
AND HELP HER OUT.
PERFECT, THANK YOU.
NOW I FEEL ODD,
THEY'RE BOTH TALLER THAN ME.
WE'RE GONNA COOK EVERYTHING
ABOUT 10 TO 12 MINUTES.
COOK THE BEEF
'TIL IT'S MEDIUM-WELL
BECAUSE I'M GONNA
KEEP COOKING IT AFTER THAT.
TOMATOES --
WOULD YOU LIKE TO DO IT?
MAY I?
DO THE HONORS,
THERE WE GO.
SOMETIMES YOU EVEN WONDER
IF YOU'RE EVER NEEDED.
I'M GONNA GO WITH BEANS,
WATER TO LOOSEN IT UP
BEFORE I PUT
THE TOMATO PASTE IN.
YOU WANT TO START HANDING ME
SOME SPICES?
THE CHILI POWDER FIRST.
IT'S KIND OF MILD CHILI POWDER.
CUMIN?
YEAH.
WHITE PEPPER, GARLIC POWDER.
THIS IS CAYENNE.
I'M GONNA WAIT A WHILE
TO ADD SOME SALT.
THERE'S SALT IN
THE CHILI POWDER ALREADY.
I'M GONNA COOK IT FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR AND 15 MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA PILE THIS
ON TOP OF SOME BURGERS?
YES, SIX-OUNCE BURGERS.
(Sara)
WHAT'S YOUR PREFERRED
BURGER TEMP?
MEDIUM-RARE.
SO WE'RE MAKING
A MONSTER BURGER.
(Kenny)
TWO PATTIES,
PUT ONE RIGHT HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT SHOULD I DO WITH THIS?
WE'RE GOING OVER TO THE CHILI.
(Kenny)
OVER TO THE CHILI,
THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU SIR,
MONSTER CHILI CHEESEBURGER.
THAT A BOY.
YOU ARE A RAIDER.
(Guy)
I'M GONNA TELL YOU THIS,
IT'S GOT SOME GREAT CHILI.
THANK YOU.
REALLY NICE, GOOD SPICE TO IT
AND IT'S CREAMY.
DO YOU LIKE THAT?
I DO LIKE THAT.
THAT'S A GOOD TAILGATE
CHILI BURGER.
THE KICKER ON THIS...
CHILI'S THE KICKER.
THANK YOU DOLL.
THANK YOU.
AND HOW MANY OTHER WAYS
DO YOU MAKE BURGERS?
ALMOST 20.
(Guy)
THEY'RE THE RUDY SIGNATURE.
AND THIS ONE'S BIG
FOR BREAKFAST
ALONG WITH ALL THE CLASSICS.
IT'S KIND OF THEIR TAKE
ON EGGS BENEDICT.
(Guy)
AND ALL KINDS OF COMFORT FOOD.
BUT THE TOP OF
THE FOOD CHAIN HERE
IS STILL THE BURGER.
CAJUN BLUE BURGER,
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
WHAT MAKES IT CAJUN?
CAJUN SPICE.
START WITH A LITTLE CANOLA OIL
AND SOME ONIONS.
APPLE-SMOKED BACON,
A LITTLE SALT.
THROW IN A LITTLE PEPPER.
I'M GONNA MIX UP
SOME CAJUN SPICE.
HOW 'BOUT WE MAKE KENNY DO IT?
ALL RIGHT.
COACH ME.
FIRST YOU'RE GONNA PUT IN
SOME PAPRIKA.
IS THIS A LEFT-HANDED DEAL?
IT CAN BE.
THOSE ARE MULTI-HANDED.
GO WITH SOME GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER.
(Guy)
THAT IS A LOT OF SPICE.
IT'S NOT ALL GOING ON ONE.
OKAY, GOOD.
GO WITH SOME SALT.
THIS IS YOUR SPICE MIXTURE?
YES.
SOME OREGANO, WHITE PEPPER.
HOW ARE WE DOING SO FAR?
YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
CAYENNE PEPPER.
KIND OF SPICY, HUH,
HERE COMES THE BURGERS.
(Guy)
HOW MANY ARE YOU PUTTING ON?
I'M GONNA START
WITH ABOUT EIGHT.
I'M GONNA FEED THE FANS.
PUT CAJUN SPICE ON THERE.
(Guy)
SO WE GET THE BUNS TOASTED UP.
YOU WANT KENNY AND I
TO GET THESE OFF OF HERE?
THAT WOULD BE GREAT.
(Guy)
SNAKE, I'LL HOLD, YOUI GOT 'EM.
WE'VE GOT BLUE CHEESE,
LOTS OF BLUE CHEESE,
NO SKIMPING.
BACON.
THEN WE'VE GOT GRILLED ONIONS.
OH BOY, THAT'S MAKE
A LINEBACKER OUT OF YOU.
AND THEN LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
THOUSAND ISLAND.
I SAW AN EARLIER SHOW
YOU HAD A FORUM THAT
YOU EAT WITH.
(Guy)
YEAH, YOU HAVE TO DO THE HUNCH.
IS IT TWO-HAND?
YEAH, TWO-HAND.
YOU GET IN LIKE THIS.
ELBOW TO ELBOW?
YEAH, OKAY.
UP ON TOP AND MAKE SURE
IT DOESN'T DRIP, OKAY?
THERE WE GO.
GOOD BURGER, HUH?
VERY GOOD.
THAT'S A DRIPPY, JUICY BURGER,
BIG THICK BACON, RED ONION.
NICE SWEETNESS,
NICE BLUE CHEESE.
YOU GET SOME SWEETNESS,
SOME SALTY CRUNCH
OUT OF THE BACON.
THAT'S A TAILGATE BURGER 101.
VERY GOOD,
THANK YOU DOLL.
THANK YOU.
YOU GUYS WANT SOME BURGERS
BY KENNY STABLER?
(tailgaters cheering)
HERE YOU GUYS GO,
THE CAJUN BIG BLUE BURGER.
LET ME SLING A LITTLE CHILI.
WHAT DO YOU GUYS THINK OF
THAT ONE?
(tailgaters chanting)
DID YOU SEE THAT?
THERE WE GO,
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
(Guy)
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
THE BURGER?
IT'S GOOD.
IT WAS AWESOME, MAN.
IS THIS THE RESPONSE
THAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
WHEN YOU MAKE BURGERS?
ABSOLUTELY.
(Guy)
OKAY, YOU GUYS CONTINUE
TO ENJOY THE BURGERS.
STABLER, YOU GONNA HANG OUT
WITH THESE GUYS?
I'M GONNA HANG WITH THIS CREW.
I'LL CATCH UP WITH YOU
IN A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT,
WHEN WE COME BACK
I'M GONNA GO SEE A GUY
ABOUT A SMOKED PORK CHOP
THAT IS OFF THE HOOK.
THEY'RE READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA FINISH 'EM OFF
ON THE GRILL.
WE BRINED THEM SO YOU KNOW
THEY GOTTA BE SUPER MOIST.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
OUTSTANDING PORK CHOP.
WELCOME BACK
TO "TRIPLE-D" GONE TAILGATING.
HERE WE ARE AT THE COLISEUM,
HOME OF MY OAKLAND RAIDERS
TO MEET A DUDE THAT'S MAKING
A STEAK SANDWICH WITH,
GET THIS, JALAPENO PESTO.
IT'S THE KIND OF COMFORT FOOD
RICK LAUER'S BEEN CRANKING OUT
AT RICK AND ANN'S
IN BERKELEY FOR YEARS.
FAVORITES LIKE MAC-AND-CHEESE,
MEATLOAF,
AND SERIOUS BREAKFASTS.
IT'S GOOD FOR A DAY
WHEN YOU NEED A HEARTY
BREAKFAST OR A LUNCH.
(man)
CHEESE AND SWEET PEPPERS.
I'VE HAD ALMOST
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
(Guy)
SO 20 YEARS OF
DOING COMFORT FOOD
AT RICK AND ANN'S,
CHEF RICK LAUER,
HOW ARE YOU, BUDDY?
GOOD, GUY,
HOW YOU DOING?
I'M DOING GOOD.
THE FIRST THING
WE'RE GONNA START OFF WITH IS
A STEAK SANDWICH MADE WITH WHAT?
JALAPENO PESTO.
THAT'S A FIRST,
LET'S DO THIS.
HERE'S A NICE PIECE OF
FLANK STEAK.
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE IT.
WE'LL DRIZZLE A LITTLE BIT OF
OLIVE OIL ON IT, EXTRA-VIRGIN.
YOU CAN USE REGULAR OLIVE OIL,
YOU CAN USE CANOLA OIL.
OR 10-40 PENZOIL.
A LITTLE FRESH GARLIC.
SPRINKLE SOME KOSHER SALT,
FRESHLY GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
PAPRIKA, KIND OF
RUB IT IN THERE.
SO WE'LL LET THIS HANG OUT
FOR A FEW HOURS IN THE FRIDGE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME JALAPENO PESTO.
THERE'S NOTHING ABOUT THAT
I DON'T LIKE THE SOUND OF.
YEAH, I KEEP THIS IN MY CAR.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN YOU'RE GONNA
NEED A FOOD PROCESSOR HERE
AT THE TAILGATING EVENT.
A LITTLE CILANTRO.
JALAPENOS,
KEEP THE SEEDS IN FOR HEAT.
SOME WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES,
VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
GRATED PARMESAN.
FRESH LEMON JUICE, THAT ACID
HELPS KEEP IT NICE AND BRIGHT.
LET'S TOSS IT.
THE FLAVORS WILL MARRY
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
GET THE STEAK ON,
BUT HERE'S THE KEY
WHEN IT COMES TO FLANK STEAK.
DON'T OVERCOOK IT,
OTHERWISE YOU'RE GONNA GET
YOURSELF A TOUGH PIECE OF MEAT.
WHAT DO WE WORK ON NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA SAUTE SOME PEPPERS
FOR THE SANDWICH.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
SOME CANOLA OIL.
SLICED WHITE ONIONS.
THE ONIONS COOK DOWN,
NOW WE HIT THE PEPPERS.
YEAH, SLICED GREEN PEPPERS,
SWEET RED PEPPERS,
AND THEN SOME YELLOW PEPPERS.
A LITTLE SALT.
A LITTLE FRESH,
GROUND, BLACK PEPPER.
GA-GA-GA-GA-GA-GA-GA-GA.
THIS IS WHAT YOU GOTTA LOVE
ABOUT A RAIDER GAME, MAN.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT.
OKAY, THE PEPPERS ARE DONE,
NOW WE CAN BUILD THIS SANDWICH.
ONE MORE THING, THOUGH.
WE ADD SOME JACK CHEESE
TO THE PEPPERS, WE'RE DONE.
OH, THE JUICE
COMING OFF OF THAT.
JUST GIVE IT FIVE MINUTES
SO THE JUICES CALM DOWN.
EXACTLY.
LET'S DO SOME SLICING HERE.
ARE THOSE YOUR KEYS
OVER THERE ON THE GROUND?
MY KEYS?
I DON'T SEE ANY KEYS, GUY.
THAT'S GOOD.
HIT ONE OF THESE ROLLS
WITH SOME OF THE JALAPENO PESTO.
PUT THE FLANK STEAK ON,
THEN THE SAUTED PEPPERS,
ONIONS, AND JACK CHEESE ON TOP.
CUT IT IN HALF.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT,
A PICTURE-PERFECT SANDWICH.
THAT'S A GREAT SANDWICH.
YOU GET THE CARAMELIZATION OF
THE ONIONS, THE DISTINCT
BELL PEPPER,
BUT IT'S THE LITTLE BITE,
JUST THE LITTLE BITE
YOU GET FROM THAT JALAPENO.
THAT'S GREAT, MAN,
YOU'D LOVE THIS.
I BETCHA WE'VE GOT
FOUR MORE SANDWICHES
OUT OF THAT.
DO YOU WANT TO FEED SOME OF
THESE FANS NEXT TO US?
LET'S DO IT.
THEY'VE GOT SOME
MEAN-LOOKING SAUSAGE
AND I HEAR THEIR BEER'S COLD.
YOU GUYS WANT TO TRY
A KILLER STEAK SANDWICH?
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
COME OVER AND CHECK THIS OUT.
THIS IS WHAT YOU DO
HERE IN RAIDER NATION.
THIS LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
NICE FLAVOR.
THE SANDWICHES ARE GOOD?
THE PEPPERS.
THE SAUSAGE AIN'T BAD.
I'VE NEVER TASTED
THIS KIND OF STUFF
AT A TAILGATE.
THIS IS GOOD.
DON'T GO AND COOK TOO MUCH OF
YOUR OWN FOOD
BECAUSE WE'VE GOT
PORK CHOPS COMING UP.
WE GOT ENOUGH PORK CHOPS
FOR THEM?
WE SURE DO, GUY.
SO FIRST
WE BRINE THE PORK CHOPS.
WE START WITH SOME COLD WATER
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
KOSHER SALT,
GRANULATED WHITE SUGAR.
YOU COULD USE BROWN SUGAR,
WHITE SUGAR, MOLASSES,
HONEY.
LET IT ALL DISSOLVE IN THERE.
THEN WE ADD OUR BAY LEAF,
FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
JUNIPER BERRY IN THERE.
YEAH, CRACK IT IN
A FOOD PROCESSOR FIRST.
A LITTLE RED CHILI FLAKE,
MY FAVORITE, GARLIC.
GIVE THAT A STIR.
POP THESE BAD BOYS IN.
WE'LL LET THIS STAY REFRIGERATED
ABOUT 12 HOURS AND THOSE WILL
BRINE UP NICE.
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE IT?
ON A TABLE-TOP SMOKER.
THESE ARE APPLEWOOD CHIPS,
COVER THE BOTTOM.
THEN WE JUST PUT THE PAN
ON TOP OF THE WOOD CHIPS.
THAT KEEPS THEM
FROM CATCHING ON FIRE.
NOW WE PUT THE PORK CHOPS
IN THE SMOKER.
REALLY STARTING TO GET SOME OF
THAT SMOKE OUT OF THOSE CHOPS.
THEY'RE READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA FINISH 'EM OFF
ON THE GRILL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE POTATO PANCAKE.
FIRST WE START OUT
WITH SHREDDED POTATOES.
THAT YOU SOAKED IN WATER
SO THEY DIDN'T GO GRAY ON YOU.
THEN WE'RE GONNA CRACK ONE EGG,
SOME GRATED ONION,
PANKO BREADCRUMBS.
MIX THAT TOGETHER, YOU'VE GOT
A LITTLE BINDER OF THE EGG.
WE'RE READY TO PUT IT
ON THE GRIDDLE.
JUST PLOP THEM RIGHT ON.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME SALT
AND PEPPER ON, CANOLA OIL,
AND IT'LL HELP BROWN 'EM UP.
FINISH 'EM OFF
WITH SOME CHEDDAR
AND JACK CHEESE ON HERE.
COVER 'EM WITH A SHEET PAN.
LET'S DO IT.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THE CHOPS ARE DONE.
WE BRINED 'EM
SO YOU KNOW THEY'VE
GOTTA BE SUPER MOIST.
PUT ON SOME HOMEMADE APPLESAUCE
AND A SCOOP OF SOUR CREAM.
A LITTLE BIT OF GREEN ONION
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THIS CHOP
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
OUTSTANDING PORK CHOP.
THAT IS THE PERFECT AMOUNT
OF SMOKE.
THAT REMINDS ME
A LITTLE BIT OF BACON.
PROBABLY THE TOP FIVE
BEST PORK CHOPS I'VE EVER HAD.
AND THE PANCAKE --
KILLER CRUNCH, DYNAMITE.
I THINK THOSE PEOPLE BACK THERE
ARE GONNA BE EXPECTING SOME
PORK CHOP AND PANCAKES.
HE'S GONNA DISH UP
THE PORK CHOPS AND PANCAKE.
AND ME, I'M GONNA GO OUT THERE
AND CHECK OUT THE REST OF
THIS TAILGATING ADVENTURE
AND SEE IF ANYBODY
CAN STAND UP TO THAT CHOP.
GREAT JOB BROTHER.
THANKS, GUY.
WE GOT CHICKEN, WE GOT STEAK,
WE GOT EVERYTHING YOU NEED.
IT IS GOOD FOOD,
IT IS GOOD TIMES.
(Guy)
SO HERE WE ARE,
OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA
HANGING OUT
WITH THE RAIDER LEGEND
KENNY STABLER.
NOW SNAKE AND I ARE CHECKING OUT
ALL THE TAILGATING
"TRIPLE-D" STYLE.
WE'VE GOT CHICKEN,
WE'VE GOT STEAK.
WE'VE GOT EVERYTHING YOU NEED.
(Guy)
EVERY WEEK THE PARKING LOT'S
LOADED WITH THOUSANDS OF FANS
COOKING IT UP
THOUSANDS OF WAYS.
GOING CULINARY AT A TAILGATE,
DIG IT.
NOW THIS IS THE MAN
RIGHT HERE.
SIX GRILLS EVERY WEEKEND.
CLASSIC AMERICAN DINER TODAY.
THREE KINDS OF CHEESEBURGERS.
WE'VE GOT BAKED BEANS,
WE'VE GOT CHILI.
SKEWERS,
WE'VE GOT SOME JAMBALAYA.
ONION AND GARLIC IN THE BURGERS,
WE'VE GOT SOME TRI-TIP.
HOT LINKS, CORN.
IT'S GOOD FOOD
AND IT'S GOOD TIMES.
(Guy)
AND IT'S SERIOUS TRADITION.
WE'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR THE LAST FIVE,
SIX YEARS STRONG,
EVERY SUNDAY.
WE'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR SIX YEARS.
HIS SON'S SONS WILL DO IT.
COMING TOGETHER,
HAVING A GOOD DINNER
JUST LIKE THANKSGIVING.
IT'S ALL ABOUT FAMILY.
CHILDHOOD FRIENDS,
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FRIENDS,
HIGH SCHOOL,
PEOPLE GETTING MARRIED.
FOOD BRINGS FAMILY TOGETHER.
(Guy)
LOOK AT THE LAYOUT --
MAC-AND-CHEESE, LASAGNA.
CAN I TRY A PIECE?
WE HAVE SOME TRI-TIPS.
IT'S ALL MARINATED IN ONION
AND PARSLEY AND CHILI SAUCE.
WHAT ELSE DO WE GOT?
CHICKEN, RACK OF RIBS.
NICE BRISKET,
ANOTHER RACK OF RIBS.
NOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
DO YOU GUYS FEED WITH THIS?
ABOUT 100.
SO 100 PEOPLE.
100 AND UP.
(Guy)
IMPRESSIVE.
AND GET A LOAD OF THIS CREW.
HOW MANY PEOPLE CAN YOU FEED
IN ONE EVENT?
WE'VE DONE 400 AT ONE TIME
WITHOUT A PROBLEM.
THESE GUYS ARE LIKE A FIXTURE,
THEY'VE BEEN HERE SINCE '95,
KIRK BRONSORD
AND THE BAD BOYS OF BBQ.
SALMON, PRIME RIB,
PULLED PORK, BABY BACK RIBS,
CHICKEN THIGHS, SKIRT STEAK,
OYSTERS.
DUDE, NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
WHAT KIND OF CHICKEN IS THAT?
SOY AND GINGER.
IS THAT A RIB, OR WHAT?
REALLY GOOD, GREAT RIBS.
I SEE WHY THEY CALL YOU
THE BARBECUE BAD BOYS.
EVERY TIME I COME HERE
I'M BLOWN AWAY BY THESE GUYS.
OUTSTANDING.
A LITTLE PULLED PORK,
LET'S TRY IT.
(Guy)
WE'RE GONNA WEIGH 400 POUNDS
WHEN WE WALK OUT OF HERE.
THIS PRIME RIB IS 12 POUNDS.
IT'S GOT A FRESH GARLIC
AND HERB CRUST ON IT.
LET'S TRY A PIECE OF PRIME RIB.
SUPER-TENDER PRIME RIB.
THE PULLED PORK
IN THE BIG 50-GALLON DRUM.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE
OUT OF ALL OF THAT?
THIS CHICKEN.
(Guy)
NEXT TIME I COME FOR A HOME GAME
THIS IS WHERE I'M COMING TO EAT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, SNAKE?
YOU BET,
WAY TO GO BAD BOY.
KIRK, THANK YOU MAN.
OUR PLEASURE.
SNAKE, IT'S BEEN A BLAST
HAVING YOU ON THIS.
SO LISTEN, THAT WRAPS UP
"TRIPLE-D" TAILGATING
HERE IN RAIDER NATION.
BUT YOU WATCH OUT,
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU NEXT
ON "DINER'S,
DRIVE-IN'S, AND DIVES."
SEE YOU LATER.
Closed Captioning Provided by
Scripps Networks, LLC