HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MMM. I ATE
THE WHOLE THING.
FRESH...
(Guy) HOW MUCH
ARE YOU GUYS
MAKIN' FROM SCRATCH
YOURSELF?
I'D SAY ABOUT 95%.
REALLY?
MM-HMM.
AND FUNKY...
(woman) DUCK POPPERS.
I NEVER HAD THESE.
IN CHARLOTTE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD
HOME-COOKED FOOD HERE.
THE LOCAL LANDMARK...
WHATEVER YOU'RE
IN THE MOOD FOR.
WITH A MENU
FROM EVERYWHERE...
FROM ITALIAN
TO AMERICAN--
THE GREEK.
AND TURKEY DONE THEIR WAY.
YOU BOIL THE TURKEY?
BOIL THE TURKEY.
IN RENO...
HEY, Y'ALL.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD CAFé...
EVERYTHING SHE HAS
IS SOMETHING MOM MADE,
BUT ALWAYS BETTER.
WHERE IT'S LIKE
EATING AT HOME.
ENJOY YOUR LUNCH.
AND THAT MEANS...
WELL, YOU COME OUT HERE
ON THE LITTLE PATIO
AND HAVE A BARBECUE,
AND THAT'S OKAY.
YEAH.
GRILLIN' OUT BACK.
OH, CAN'T BEAT THAT.
DEFINITELY.
AND IN SAN FRANCISCO...
RIGHT HERE
IN THE SUNSHINE
THE PARTY ON THE PIER...
THE ATMOSPHERE.
WHERE THE SEAFOOD
IS THE FRESHEST.
SEA MUSSELS AND CLAMS IN
A WHITE WINE AND GARLIC SAUCE--
PHENOMENAL.
AND THEY'RE DOING DUCK
WITH A TWIST.
WRAPPED
WITH, UH, BACON.
(Guy)
THESE BAD BOYS READY?
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
MMM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
FOR FOLKS WHO TRAVEL A LOT,
THEY HAVE THEIR OASES,
LIKE, FAVORITE HOTEL,
FAVORITE CAR RENTAL
AND FAVORITE RESTAURANTS.
BUT FOR FOLKS
FROM THE EAST COAST,
IT'S NOT JUST FAVORITE
RESTAURANTS,
IT'S FAVORITE DINERS,
AND NOT JUST DINERS,
BUT GREEK FAMILY-RUN DINERS.
WELL, HERE'S THE OASIS
IN CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA--
LANDMARK DINER.
(man) ROAST TURKEY!
TURKEY AND STUFFING--
MAKES ME FEEL WARM INSIDE.
I LOVE THE REUBENS.
WHATEVER YOU'RE
IN THE MOOD FOR.
FROM ITALIAN TO AMERICAN--
THE GREEK.
(man) GREEK SALAD'S UP!
THERE'S REALLY GOOD
HOME-COOKED FOOD HERE.
THAT HEAD CHEF
MILTON POLEMIDES...
HOME FRIES!
PICKED UP
FROM HIS FATHER-IN-LAW
JOHN KALTSOUNIS...
GIVE ME ANOTHER
SPINACH PIE.
AN EX-NEW YORKER WHO OPENED
THIS JOINT 20 YEARS AGO
WITH HIS BROTHER LARRY.
A LOT OF GREEK FAMILY DINERS
HERE IN CHARLOTTE?
WE'RE THE FIRST ONE
WERE HERE.
THE FIRST
TO INTRODUCE CHARLOTTE
TO NORTHEAST DINER
CLASSICS...
(Milton)
SPLIT-PEA SOUP!
LIKE THANKSGIVING
ON A PLATE...
ROAST TURKEY.
DONE THE LANDMARK WAY.
WHAT IS
THE BIG STOCKPOT FOR?
WELL, THAT'S THE, UH,
FUNNY THING HERE.
WE BOIL OUR TURKEYS.
YOU BOIL THE TURKEY?
BOIL THE TURKEY.
WE DON'T ROAST IT.
START OFF WITH SOME
ONIONS, CELERY,
THEN CARROTS.
IT'S SURE GONNA CHANGE
YOUR THANKSGIVING, AIN'T IT?
THROW IN A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPER AND NOW SALT.
PUT IN OUR WATER.
HE PICKED UP, LIKE,
A 5-GALLON BUCKET OF WATER
LIKE HE WAS DUMPIN' OVER
A CUP OF COFFEE.
NOW YOU'RE JUST GONNA MANHANDLE
THIS OVER TO THE STOVE.
OH, YEAH.
THIS BOILS FOR ABOUT TWO,
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
GET DONE, COOL DOWN
A LITTLE BIT--
WELL, HOW DO WE MAKE A GRAVY,
IF THERE'S NO PAN DRIPPINGS?
FROM THE STOCK.
BUTTER--LET THAT MELT.
ADD OUR FLOUR.
MIX. LET THE FLOUR
COOK A LITTLE BIT.
ADD OUR TURKEY STOCK.
WHISK IT TOGETHER.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
BLACK PEPPER--WHISK. VOILà.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR STUFFING--
A LITTLE BIT OF VEGETABLE OIL,
ONIONS, OUR CELERY,
MY CARROT,
AND I'M GONNA LET THEM
COOK DOWN PRETTY GOOD BIT.
WHAT ELSE DO WE HAVE
GOIN' IN THERE?
A POUND OF BUTTER,
APPLE MIXTURE.
THIS IS MADE
FROM MY DEAR OLD BAKER.
I REALLY DON'T KNOW WHERE
WE'RE GOING AT THIS POINT.
THROW IN MY GARLIC,
MY SAGE.
WHOA, THE WHOLE GARDEN,
HUH, BROTHER?
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER,
SALT, A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH
IN THE APPLE PIE FILLING?
NO.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF POULTRY SEASONING,
AND WE MIX THAT.
SUGAR.
LET THAT COOK DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE BREADCRUMB MIXTURE
THAT I MAKE WITH CHALLAH BREAD,
WHICH IS MADE HERE.
THROW THIS IN MY POT.
THEN WE'LL ADD THE EGGS,
A LITTLE BIT OF TURKEY STOCK.
THEN WE'LL MIX IT A LITTLE BIT.
HOLD IT?
NO, ACTUALLY,
I'LL LEAVE IT...
OH.
I'LL LEAVE IT SO I TURN IT
AS I KNEAD IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE VEGGIE MIXTURE.
GET IT ALL?
COMBINE EVERYTHING.
ROWING DOWN THE RIVER
RIGHT NOW?
EXACTLY. READY TO GO.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA
COAT OUR PAN.
WITH A LITTLE
AQUA NET.
NOW LET'S MAKE
SOME STUFFING.
OKAY.
SO IT'S STUFFING,
UM, UH, LOAF.
HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA GO?
WE'LL THROW IT IN.
IT'S GONNA GO ABOUT, UH,
45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR.
45 TO AN HOUR--
BRING IT OUT.
LOOK AT THAT NICE CRUNCH
ON TOP... (whistles)
LET'S CUT THE STUFFING.
THAT IS DENSE.
WE ALWAYS COAT THIS
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF GRAVY.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND CLEAN THE TURKEY.
OKAY.
NOW THIS IS THE NON-ROASTED
TURKEY. THIS IS BOILED.
CARVE YOU OFF A PIECE.
I'LL DIP IT IN THE STOCK...
THAT IT COOKED IN.
MAKE SURE IT'S NICE AND HOT,
AND THEN WE PUT IT ON TOP.
OKAY.
AND NOW TO YOUR GRAVY,
TOP IT ONE MORE TIME.
MORE GRAVY?
A LITTLE BIT
OF GRAVY ON TOP.
THAT'S A GOOD-NIGHT MEAL
RIGHT THERE.
HMM, WELL, THAT'S
BIG FLAVOR, MAN--
TENDER TURKEY,
BIG FLAVOR IN THE GRAVY. MMM.
HOW'S THE STUFFING?
I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
MAN, IT'S GOOD.
I DIDN'T THINK YOU WERE GONNA
PULL IT OFF WITH THOSE APPLES.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M PICKING UP
IS THE CINNAMON. HMM.
IT'S THANKSGIVING ON A PLATE
EVERY DAY. WAY TO GO.
THANK YOU.
ROAST TURKEY
WITH STUFFING.
THE TURKEY IS MOIST.
THE GRAVY IS EXCELLENT.
THE STUFFING IS GOOD.
APPLE PIE FILLING.
HE TASTED
SOMETHING SWEET.
OOH.
I THOUGHT IT WAS
GINGERBREAD, ACTUALLY.
OH, HO.
THEY HAVE
THE BEST FOOD. MMM.
YOU CAN GO BREAKFAST,
LUNCH, DINNER.
CHEESEBURGER
DELUXE.
DID YOU SEE THE DESSERTS
WHEN YOU CAME IN?
NO.
THERE'S DESSERTS, TOO?
OH, YES.
ALL THE FAN FAVORITES,
FROM CHEESECAKE
TO CHOCOLATE MOUSSE CAKE.
CHERRY TURNOVERS
THE SIZE OF YOUR HEAD.
AND BROTHER LARRY IS
SCRATCH-MAKIN' IT ALL.
HOW MANY THINGS DO YOU
BAKE IN--UH, EVERY DAY.
230 ITEMS.
UH, THE MENU
IS GINORMOUS.
THERE'S SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY, REALLY.
(speaking indistinctly)
FROM CHICKEN PARMESAN
TO MEATLOAF MARSALA
AND GREEK FAMILY FAVORITES
LIKE THIS ONE.
SPANAKOPITA.
SPANAKOPITA--
SPINACH PIE.
WELL, THIS IS
WHAT I GREW UP ON.
OH, BOY.
WE START OFF WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF VEGETABLE.
WHITE ONION.
CHOPPED GREEN ONIONS
AND DILL.
DILL?
DILL. IT GIVES IT
A VERY UNIQUE TASTE.
SO WE SWEAT THIS DOWN.
YES.
AND WHAT'S GONNA BE
OUR NEXT STEP?
THE EGGS--MIX 'EM
WITH MY SPINACH.
(Guy) OKAY.
(Milton) MY FETA.
NICE.
A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT, PEPPER,
AND THEN THE ONION
AND DILL MIXTURE.
WE'RE GONNA
MIX THIS UP.
I'M LIKIN'
THE MIXTURE SMELL.
NOW HERE COMES THE...
PHYLLO DOUGH.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL--
COAT THE BAKING SHEET.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
LAYERING THE PHYLLO DOUGH.
OLIVE OIL.
YOU'VE GOT, LIKE,
EIGHT SHEETS,
SO A NICE, BIG,
CRUSTY BOTTOM.
YES, SIR.
OKAY.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH ONE LAYER OF THE MIX.
PICASSO, BREATHE
BETWEEN THIS, ALL RIGHT?
I'M BREATHIN',
I'M BREATHIN'.
THIS DUDE'S
FULL SPEED.
ANOTHER LAYER OF PHYLLO DOUGH,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER
AND ANOTHER LAYER
OF SPINACH MIX.
I'M GONNA START
WITH THE TOP LAYER.
TOP GONNA BE
LIKE THE BOTTOM?
THE TOP IS GONNA BE
MORE PHYLLO.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
FOLD THIS OVER.
I'LL THROW THE LAST
OF THE OLIVE OIL ON THERE.
NOW I'M GONNA CUT THIS.
HOW MANY PIECES
WE GETTIN' OUT OF THIS?
36 INDIVIDUAL PORTIONS.
OKAY.
PUT THIS IN THE OVEN,
AROUND 400.
HOW LONG?
45 TO AN HOUR.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
PULL IT.
(whistles)
WE DO NEED
TO RECUT THIS.
AND WE'LL GET YOU
A NICE CORNER PIECE.
SEE, I LIKE THE EDGE.
PHYLLO--YES, THAT WAS
ALWAYS MY FAVORITE.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
THE DILL--
THE DILL ACTUALLY
REALLY MAKES THAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT DOES?
IT COMPLEMENTS REALLY NICE
WITH THE FETA. MMM.
THAT'S GOOD, DUDE.
IT'S SIMPLE, DONE RIGHT.
I'LL EAT THAT AGAIN.
I'D EAT THAT...
36 MORE TIMES.
(Milton)
SPINACH PIE DINNER!
IT'S NICE AND CREAMY,
LIKE QUICHE.
AND I LOVE THE LAYERS
OF THE CRUST--VERY TASTY. MMM.
FETA GOING DOWN--
GREEK OMELET.
THIS IS PROBABLY
THE ONLY PLACE AROUND
THAT CAN SAY THEY'RE A DINER,
AND THEY ARE A DINER.
THE MAN.
(Milton) CHICKEN TIPS.
THANK YOU.
REALLY GOOD, MAN.
NICE JOB. VERY NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
HEY, Y'ALL
WE'RE HEADIN'
WEST TO RENO...
WHOO, I ALMOST LOST IT.
YOU ENJOY THIS,
DON'T YOU?
I DO.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
WE PUT GLOVES ON,
STIR IT UP,
'CAUSE IT'S
PRETTY STICKY.
HOMEMADE GRANOLA.
GOOD GRANOLA GIRL.
GRANOLA. YAY.
ABOUT A MILE SOUTHEAST
OF DOWNTOWN RENO
IS A PLACE THAT WAS
ONCE DOCTOR'S OFFICES
AND THEN GOT CONVERTED
INTO A COFFEE SHOP.
AND NOW IT'S HOME TO A CAFé
THAT'S ALL ABOUT ORGANICS
AND FARM-TO-TABLE
AND LOCAL, SEASONAL EATING.
AND GET THIS--
THEY DO ALL OF THIS
IN AN 84-SQUARE-FOOT KITCHEN.
THIS IS DISH CAFé.
CUP OF...
THAT'S RIGHT THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S A TINY PLACE.
WATCH OUT.
THE KITCHEN'S SO SMALL...
LOOK OUT.
YOU GOTTA GO OUTSIDE TO CHANGE
YOUR MIND, WHICH IS GOOD,
'CAUSE THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE
DOING A LOT OF THE COOKING.
THEY'RE GRILLIN' THE TRI-TIP
AS YOU WALK IN THE FRONT DOOR.
HEY, Y'ALL.
AND THEIR RINGMASTER HERE...
WANT TO CHECK
THOSE OUT?
OWNER NANCY HORN,
A FORMER ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ART TEACHER...
GOT TWO SPECIALS.
WHO TRADED IN HER CRAYONS
AND SCISSORS...
ENJOY YOUR LUNCH.
FOR TONGS AND MIXING BOWLS.
WHOO, I ALMOST LOST IT.
YOU ENJOY THIS,
DON'T YOU?
I DO. IT'S--I ALWAYS
WANTED A RESTAURANT.
ORDER UP.
SHE'LL DO ALL KINDS
OF DIFFERENT THINGS.
(woman)
QUICHES ARE AWESOME...
MMM.
GOOD SOUP SPECIALS,
REALLY GOOD SANDWICHES.
LIKE THIS SPECIAL
THAT'S PACKING 'EM IN.
MMM.
COWGIRL TRI-TIP PANINI.
CAN'T CALL IT THE TRI-TIP
PRESSED PANINI--NO, NO.
YOU HAVE TO CALL IT
THE--SHOW 'EM.
WHOO, WHOO--
THE COWGIRL.
THAT'S HOW
YOU ORDER IT HERE.
WHAT ARE WE INTO FIRST?
WE ARE GONNA MAKE
THE TRI-TIP RUB.
OKAY, GO.
GROUND PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
ONION POWDER,
IODIZED SALT.
WHY IODIZED?
IT'S JUST MORE CONCENTRATED
SALT FLAVOR. ITALIAN HERBS.
GRIND SOME ESPRESSO--
GOOD FOR ABOUT THREE SHOTS.
THAT GOES IN THERE.
ESPRESSO GRIND BEANS
REALLY COMPLEMENTS THE FAT
IN THE MEAT...
IT DOES.
TRI-TIP--
WORKS OUT GREAT.
THEN MIX IT UP.
OKAY, SO YOU BREAK DOWN THOSE
LITTLE CHUNKS OF PAPRIKA.
WE DO.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'VE GOT
THE, UH, DRY RUB.
WE'VE GOT THE DRY RUB.
THEN WE PUT THE TIP
IN HERE. PRESS DOWN.
WE COVER IT COMPLETELY
AND RUB IT IN REALLY WELL.
ALL RUBBED,
READY TO GO.
DONE, READY TO GO.
THE ONLY QUESTION I HAVE IS
I REALLY DON'T BELIEVE WE'RE
DOING IT ON THESE PANINI GRILLS.
WE'RE NOT.
WE'RE GONNA
HAVE TO GO OUTSIDE.
WE'RE GOING
ON A FIELD TRIP.
WE ARE.
SO YOU CAN COME OUT HERE
ON THE LITTLE PATIO
AND HAVE A LITTLE BARBECUE,
AND THAT'S OKAY.
YEAH.
OH, CAN'T BEAT THAT.
DEFINITELY. PRETTY HOT--
500 DEGREES.
AND WE'RE GONNA LAY IT DOWN
SEVEN MINUTES PER SIDE.
HOW'S IT LOOK?
LOOKIN' PERFECT,
READY TO FLIP.
OKAY, READY?
YEP.
ALL RIGHT. SO BRING IT IN,
REFRIGERATE IT OVERNIGHT...
YEP.
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T JUST
SLICE 'EM. IT'LL...
SLICE 'EM--EXACTLY.
LOSE ALL THE JUICE.
YES.
INTO THE SLICER--
SLICE AWAY.
YES.
AND WE LIKE TO SLICE IT
REALLY THIN.
SOMEBODY IS OVER THERE
BANGING ON THE WINDOW,
TRYING TO GET
YOUR ATTENTION.
(laughter)
NO? THEY LEFT.
MMM.
THAT'S REALLY PERFECT.
YOU SHOULDN'T CALL
THIS SANDWICH THE COWGIRL.
YOU SHOULD CALL IT
THE KING KONG. LOOK AT THAT.
MEDIUM RARE, GOOD CRUST ON IT--
MMM, THAT'S THE FIRST TASTE
I GOT TO HAVE OF THAT.
THAT IS AWESOME.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUR BREAD--
SOURDOUGH--
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA JUST START
BUILDING--A LITTLE BIG OF DIJON.
SO THEN GOAT CHEESE.
SOUR CREAM.
DIJON, SALT AND PEPPER--
BLEND IT UP.
BLEND IT UP--
GOAT CHEESE SPREAD.
(whistles)
AND THEN WE PUT
SOME TRI-TIP ON THERE.
I'M GONNA MAKE
THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
WE START WITH SOME BUTTER,
OLIVE OIL,
SOME SLICED SPANISH ONIONS,
KOSHER SALT,
THEN SOME CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
AND WE'RE GONNA COOK THAT
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES,
SO IT'S REALLY CARAMELIZED.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME FRESH THYME,
AND WE'RE NOT GONNA
COOK THAT IN,
BECAUSE THAT COOKS WHEN WE MAKE
THE PANINI ON THE GRILL.
PUT THE LID ON IT.
TIME TO GRILL IT.
RUN THE TEMPERATURE
AT WHAT?
450. IT TAKES
ABOUT 10 MINUTES.
HERE WE GO.
SEE, THAT'S WHAT I LIKE--
REALLY CRUSTY.
WE DON'T PUT BUTTER OR OIL.
SO WE'RE READY TO EAT IT.
JUST GIVE IT A BIG CHOP.
HERE WE GO.
MMM, GREAT SANDWICH.
IT MAY BE THIN,
BUT IT'S PACKED.
MM-HMM.
YOU GOT THE NICE, SWEET FLAVOR
OF THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
THE COOKED,
GRILLED MEAT TASTE.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
GOAT CHEESE BITTERNESS...
MM-HMM.
WITHOUT IT BEING OVERPOWERING.
IT'S DONE RIGHT.
(woman)
COWGIRL PANINI.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
THE GOAT CHEESE ON THERE
MAKES IT VERY, VERY CREAMY.
(woman) IT'S GOT
THE SMOKY FLAVOR.
THE ONIONS ARE
JUST TO DIE FOR.
(man) SHE MAKES EVERYTHING.
YOU NEVER SEE ANYTHING
COME IN OR OUT OF THIS PLACE
IN A CAN OR A BOX.
ORGANIC MIXED GREENS.
I AM A BIG FAN
OF THE SALADS.
THEIR DRESSINGS
ARE ALL DELICIOUS.
MM-HMM.
HOW MUCH ARE YOU GUYS
MAKIN' FROM SCRATCH YOURSELF?
I'D SAY ABOUT 95%.
REALLY?
MM-HMM. JUST LIKE
MOM'S KITCHEN.
WHERE THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
NEARLY TWO DOZEN
DIFFERENT KINDS
OF BAKED GOODS A DAY,
AND THEY'RE
EVEN MAKING THIS.
OUR HOUSE-MADE
GRANOLA.
IT'S GOT LOTS
OF CRUNCH TO IT.
I LOVE GRANOLA.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
MY MOM WOULD MAKE
WHEN I WAS A KID.
HOW DO WE MAKE
THE DISH CAFé GRANOLA?
ORGANIC OATS.
ROLLED OATS.
ORGANIC UNSWEETENED
COCONUT,
SLICE ALMONDS--
NOT TOASTED.
BRAN CEREAL.
PURCHASED FROM THE STORE
BRAN CEREAL?
YEP.
OKAY.
I JUST TASTE EVERYTHING
TO MAKE SURE IT'S GOOD.
IT'S GOOD.
I LIKE THAT. THAT HAS
A NICE LITTLE CRUNCH TO IT.
IT'S CRUNCHY.
WHEAT GERM.
BUT YOU DON'T ALWAYS JUST GO
AND EAT WHEAT GERM,
BUT WHEN YOU CAN COMBINE IT
IN WITH THESE INGREDIENTS...
YOU MAKE IT--
IT LETS IT KIND OF RIDE ALONG
WITH EVERYTHING ELSE.
MM-HMM.
DRIED CRANBERRIES, BROWN SUGAR,
GROUND CINNAMON, GROUND GINGER,
CANOLA OIL, CANADIAN
MAPLE SYRUP,
ORGANIC VANILLA.
OKAY. VERY NICE.
AND THEN WE PUT GLOVES ON,
STIR IT UP,
'CAUSE IT'S PRETTY STICKY,
KIND OF IN A MASSAGE-Y WAY.
SO YOU'RE REALLY GETTING--
THAT WAS "MASSAGE-Y"?
MASSAGE-Y STIRRING.
OKAY.
IT'S MORE LIKE CRUNCHING
AND KNEADING AT THE SAME TIME.
I WANT EVERYTHING COATED
WITH THE OIL, THE VANILLA.
SO ONCE YOU'VE GOT IT
ALL MIXED UP,
THEN IT GOES ON
A SHEET PAN.
NOW WHAT TEMPERATURE
AND HOW LONG?
350, ABOUT 35
TO 40 MINUTES.
AND WE GIVE IT A STIR
WITH A SPATULA
ABOUT EVERY 15 MINUTES
JUST TO TURN ALL THE PIECES
AND MAKE SURE
THEY CLUMP.
AND YOU WANT
THAT CLUMPY CRUNCHY.
YOU WANT IT.
IT'S GRANOLA.
LET IT COOL
BEFORE YOU EAT IT.
MM-HMM.
OKAY. NOBODY'S
OVERBROWNED.
IT GETS
A LITTLE NUGGET-Y.
MMM.
REALLY TASTY, REMINDS ME
OF MY MOM'S GRANOLA.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE KICKER IN
THERE IS? THE BRAN CEREAL...
MM-HMM.
THE SLIVERED ALMONDS
AND THEN SOME OF THE CHEWINESS
OF THE, UH, CRANBERRIES.
PROTEIN, FIBER--
GOOD GRANOLA, GIRL.
(clicks tongue)
RIGHT ON.
GOOD GRANOLA GIRL.
GRANOLA. YAY.
DEFINITELY TASTES HOMEMADE--
I LOVE IT.
DO YOU WANT TO GET ME
THAT SOUP?
EVERYTHING SHE HAS
IS SOMETHING MOM MADE,
BUT ALWAYS BETTER.
SORRY, MOM.
AND WHO'S HAVING
THAT SCONE?
YOU JUST KEEP
COMING BACK.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, GUY.
GLAD YOU VISITED.
THANK YOU.
NEXT UP...
WE HAVE THE VIEW,
THE NICE BREEZE.
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO NORTHERN CALIFORNIA...
NO BETTER PLACE
TO UNWIND THAN PIER 23.
WHERE THE CATCH
OF THE DAY...
IT'S FRESH
MAHI MAHI.
IS HEADIN' FOR A TACO.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT HOW A LOT OF
TRIPLE "D's" GET STARTED.
WELL, IT USUALLY INVOLVES
YOU SENDING US AN E-MAIL,
AND THEN US TRYING TO TRACK
THE JOINTS DOWN,
BUT NOT THIS TIME,
NOT IN SAN FRANCISCO
ON THE EMBARCADERO.
NO, THIS BAD BOY IS ALL MINE,
'CAUSE MY CREW AND I HAVE BEEN
HANGIN' HERE FOR YEARS.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN'
FRESH SEAFOOD, LIVE MUSIC,
A HUGE PATIO,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT? GOOD TIMES.
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT
PIER 23.
♪ COME ON, COME ON,
BABY, HAVE YOU HEARD? ♪
IT'S A FUN,
OUTDOORSY BAR...
ALL RIGHT,
THE STEAMED MUSSELS.
THAT ALSO HAS
GREAT FOOD.
♪ BABE,
HAVE YOU HEARD? ♪
FISH AND CHIPS,
NO SLAW.
STEAMED MUSSELS.
REALLY TASTY,
REALLY FRESH.
GOOD FOOD, GOOD MUSIC,
GOOD COMPANY.
JUST THE KIND OF PLACE
FLICKA McGURRIN
WOULD WANT TO HANG OUT.
OH, WELL, THANK YOU.
SO SHE BOUGHT THE JOINT
25 YEARS AGO.
KEEP THE MUSIC GOING.
KEEP THE FOOD HONEST.
(Guy) TELL ME
ABOUT THAT.
FRESH, DELICIOUS
SEAFOOD.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
I LIKE THE PHILOSOPHY.
SO DOES LONG-TIME G.M.
ALLAN SPROUL.
YOU GOT CRAB CAKES
COMIN' UP?
WE LIKE TO GO OUT AND EAT.
WE LIKE TO EAT FRESH.
WE LIVE IN AN AREA WHERE WE GOT
SOME INCREDIBLE FRESH STUFF.
TO S.F.s
AND A SNAPPER SANDO.
STEAMED MUSSELS AND CLAMS IN
A WHITE WINE AND GARLIC SAUCE--
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
AND THEY'RE A LOCAL LEGEND
FOR THIS NorCal FAVORITE.
THE OVEN-ROASTED
CRAB--MMM.
THE BEST ROAST GARLIC CRAB
IN THE CITY, BAR NONE.
THIS, WITHOUT QUESTION,
IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ABOUT LIVING IN NorCal.
WE GET THIS GREAT
DUNGENESS CRAB.
HOW ARE WE GONNA
PREPARE THIS BAD BOY?
BY BOILING IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT--
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA
GO DOWN FOR, ALLAN?
ABOUT 18 MINUTES.
COOL THING ABOUT THIS IS
AFTER WE COOK THIS,
IT'S GONNA TURN
BRIGHT ORANGE.
AND THEN WE
PULL IT OUT.
WE'LL ICE-BATH IT.
TO STOP THE COOKING
PROCESS. (whistles)
LOOK AT THE COLOR
ON THAT.
ARE YOU A BODY
OR A LEG MAN?
A LEG MAN, MYSELF.
ARE YOU REALLY?
OH, YEAH.
SEE, I'M A BODY GUY.
ALL RIGHT.
SO LET IT HANG OUT WHAT?
THREE TO FIVE MINUTES.
AND THEN, UH,
WE'LL CLEAN IT.
AND WE'RE READY
TO ROLL.
OKAY, SO THIS IS THE CLAWS,
THE LEGS,
THE BODY MEAT, AND NOW
IT'S GONNA GO TO A HOT PAN.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
GET HER STARTED.
A LITTLE SALT.
SO YOU SEASON THE OIL
A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE PEPPER.
ONCE IT HEATS UP,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
FORGET IT THEN.
I WON'T HOLD THE CRAB.
(laughs) GARLIC'S
THE KEY, YOU KNOW.
WITH THIS DISH,
I WOULD EXPECT IT TO BE.
A LITTLE BIT OF CRAB.
SO THE CRAB'S
ALREADY COOKED.
AND NOW IT'S TIME TO KIND OF
FORTIFY IT WITH FLAVOR.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THIS
RIGHT NOW. WOW.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A HOT MARINADE.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT
OF PARSLEY.
WHITE WINE.
A SPLASH OF LEMON
OR TWO.
A NICE, BIG OL' PAT
OF BUTTER.
I MEAN, CAN YOU COOK IT
ANY FASTER?
YES. THEN YOU JUST GIVE IT
A LITTLE BIT OF A SET.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THAT WITH?
SOURDOUGH BREAD.
GET HER TO THE PLATE.
(exhales sharply) WHOA.
GET CARRIED AWAY THERE.
SO YOU SAY
THAT YOU'RE A LEG MAN.
GO AHEAD AND SPEND ALL DAY
ON THOSE.
(laughs)
ME, I LIKE TO GET RIGHT IN HERE
AT THAT MEAT RIGHT THERE.
MMM. THAT IS JUST AWESOME.
THIS HAS GOT
THE, UH, LEMON JUICE,
BUT IT'S ALSO GOT SOME
OF THAT GREAT CRAB FLAVOR.
AND THE WHITE WINE.
THIS IS GETTIN' MESSY.
I MEAN, THIS ISN'T
FOR THE TIMID. MMM.
(laughs)
AREN'T YOU GUYS BUSY? DON'T YOU
HAVE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO DO?
(woman) CRAB.
AND IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
IT'S ALWAYS REALLY FRESH.
THE LEMON-BUTTER-GARLIC SAUCE--
I LOVE IT.
SET UP RIGHT HERE
IN THE SUNSHINE.
JUST THE ATMOSPHERE,
THE SCENERY.
NO BETTER PLACE
TO UNWIND THAN PIER 23.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR MAHI MAHI
FISH AND CHIPS.
I LOVE
THE FISH AND CHIPS.
CALAMARI
WITH THE REUBEN SAUCE.
I LOVE THE CALAMARI HERE.
IT'S SEASONED IMPECCABLY.
AND OF COURSE,
THIS BEING CALIFORNIA...
(man) FISH TACOS.
EXCELLENT.
MADE WITH THE CATCH
OF THE DAY.
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING
WE PHONE THE FISH GUYS,
SAY, "OKAY,
WHAT DO YOU GOT?"
YOU PUT FRESH FIRST,
AND THEN RECIPE NEXT.
EXACTLY. SO WE GOT SOME
NICE, FRESH MAHI MAHI.
WE CUT OUR FISH A LITTLE BIT
BIGGER AT ABOUT 1x1,
READY TO GO
FOR THE SAUTé.
DIG IT.
A BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC--
GET THAT STARTED,
AND IN GOES THE FISH.
HOW MANY TACOS
YOU MAKIN' THERE, CAP'N?
A COUPLE.
I LIKE THIS.
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION.
IT'S PRETTY
STRAIGHTFORWARD.
LET THE FISH
DO THE TALKIN'.
SALT.
A BIT OF PEPPER.
WE'LL GO OVER HERE,
GET OUR TORTILLAS READY.
OKAY, REASON WE CUT OUR FISH
A LITTLE BIT BIGGER
IS IT DOESN'T OVERCOOK.
IT COOKS RARE.
GIVE IT A QUICK CHOP.
AND THEN WHAT REALLY SETS
OUR TACOS OFF
ARE THE FRESH CORN RELISH
AND THE HOUSE SLAW.
AND THE HOUSE SLAW--
AND YOU MAKE THE SLAW TO ORDER?
YEAH.
DICED CARROT
AND HONEY COLESLAW DRESSING.
NICE UNDERACHIEVING.
A LITTLE BIT OF FISH.
SEE HOW NICE AND RARE
THAT IS? A LITTLE QUICK FOLD...
GET THE FOLD.
GOT 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE AND TENDER IN THERE.
MM-HMM. I DON'T KNOW
THAT I'VE EVER HAD
A SEMI-RARE FISH TACO,
BUT I WILL TELL YOU,
THAT IS THE WAY
TO EAT IT.
THE SUSHI TACO.
MMM. YOU CAN TASTE THE FISH.
CORN SALSA HAS GREAT POP.
AND YOU MAKE THE SALSA, TOO.
YEP.
OF COURSE.
EVERY MORNING.
THAT'S A DYNAMITE FISH TACO.
MMM. I ATE THE WHOLE THING.
I GOTTA LAY DOWN.
THE FISH TACOS
ARE AMAZING.
FRESH, DELICIOUS--
EVERYTHING'S GOOD, THOUGH.
AND SOMETIMES
A TOTAL SURPRISE.
(woman) DUCK POPPERS.
I'VE NEVER HAD THESE.
DUCK POPPERS ARE
OUT OF THIS WORLD.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
OVEN-ROASTED CRAB.
AT PIER 23
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
WE HAVE THE VIEW,
THE NICE BREEZE
AND GREAT SEAFOOD.
AND OWNER FLICKA McGURRIN...
HAVE A FUN DAY,
YOU GUYS.
HAS KEPT A GOOD THING GOIN'
FOR 25 YEARS.
IT'S NOT HARD TO DO
IF YOU LOVE IT.
STEAMED MUSSELS.
ME, ALL MY BOYS IN THE CREW
LOVE THE 23.
THANK YOU.
I'VE HAD THE FISH TACOS.
I'VE HAD THE CRAB.
AND I'VE HAD EVERY BEER
YOU SERVE.
BUT I DID MISS
SOMETHING.
(woman)
DUCK POPPERS.
DUCK BREASTS WRAPPED
WITH, UH, BACON.
AND THEY'RE G.M. ALLAN SPROUL'S
OWN RECIPE.
DUCK POPPERS, OKAY.
DUCK POPPERS--
A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
A LITTLE CAYENNE,
A LITTLE PEPPER, SALT,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
WHISK THAT UP.
WHAT'S THIS
RIGHT HERE?
GRANULATED GARLIC.
MAKE SURE
WE DON'T MISS IT.
WHISK THAT UP REAL QUICK.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CREAM CHEESE.
MIX THAT ALL UP.
THAT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT IN IT.
CREAM CHEESE SORT OF COOLS
IT DOWN A HAIR.
MELLOWS OUT A BIT, OKAY.
EXACTLY. PUT THAT
OFF TO THE SIDE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A QUICK MARINADE. OIL--
FOR THE...
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
THE BREASTS IN IT.
OKAY.
RED WINE VINEGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
RED PEPPER FLAKE,
ITALIAN SEASONING, SALT,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
THEN YOU WHISK IT TOGETHER.
NOW WE'RE DOWN
TO THE DUCK.
SO WE START
WITH DUCK BREAST.
SLICE 'EM THIN.
GET ABOUT THREE
OUT OF EACH BREAST.
THEN YOU PUT A LITTLE
PLASTIC OVER THE TOP.
LIGHTLY POUND 'EM OUT.
SO WE'RE GONNA WRAP
THE DUCK AROUND EVERYTHING?
WE'RE GONNA WRAP THE DUCK
AROUND EVERYTHING.
I GOTTA SEE THIS.
A LITTLE SLICE OF ONION
AND FOR A LITTLE HEAT,
A LITTLE JALAPEÑO.
AND YOU CAN'T SAY "POPPER"
WITH HAVING JALAPEÑO INVOLVED.
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF THE CREAM CHEESE MIX.
THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF A ROLL,
AND OF COURSE,
A LITTLE BACON WRAP,
THEN MY PICK.
THAT'S A BIG POPPER.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS TO 'EM?
INTO THE MARINADE.
HOLY POPPER. OKAY.
FOR A COUPLE HOURS?
PUT 'EM IN THERE--
YEAH, TWO TO FOUR HOURS.
NOW THEY GO TO THE GRILL?
LET'S GO.
NOW HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA TAKE TO COOK, ALLAN?
ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
SO YOU GOTTA
KIND OF MONITOR 'EM
SO THAT BACON DOESN'T BURN UP
ON YOU. IT'LL FLARE UP.
YEAH, YOU WANT TO KEEP
SPINNING 'EM.
YOU DON'T--YOU WANT TO COOK IT
TILL THE BACON'S DONE.
AND THEN THE DUCK MEAT
WILL BE PERFECT.
WHAT DO THEY
GET SERVED WITH?
TODAY THEY'RE GETTIN' SERVED
WITH SOME COLE SLAW.
AND A SMILE.
AND A SMILE,
OF COURSE.
(bell dings)
THESE BAD BOYS READY?
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
HOLY MOLY. DUDE,
THOSE ARE HUGE.
LOOK AT THAT--EXACTLY RIGHT,
MAN. THEY ARE MEDIUM RARE.
GOTTA BE MEDIUM RARE.
MMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE TO IT,
GREAT DUCK FLAVOR--
THE BACON DOESN'T TAKE
TOO MUCH POWER AWAY.
THE ONION AND JALAPEÑO GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH INSIDE.
YEP.
THAT'S A REALLY
DYNAMITE BALANCE.
THOSE ARE ALWAYS
ON THE MENU?
NO, SPECIAL--THURSDAY,
FRIDAY, SATURDAY, SUNDAY.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH
TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY?
DUCKS NEED A DAY OFF.
NO, DUCKS DON'T. WOW.
UH...
BACON-WRAPPED DUCK POPPER--
IT'S AMAZING,
CAN'T GO WRONG
WITH BACON.
BEST COMBINATION--NEVER
THOUGHT OF IT IN MY LIFE.
THEY ALWAYS COME UP
WITH FUN SPECIALS.
HEY, KIDS,
HOW'S EVERYTHING?
GOOD.
THE FOOD IS FRESH,
DELICIOUS, FLAVORFUL.
♪ BABY, HAVE YOU HEARD ♪
YOU GET THAT,
PLUS AN ATMOSPHERE
THAT REALLY INVITES YOU
TO JUST RELAX
AND ENJOY THE DAY.
PIER 23 IS MONEY.
OKAY, THAT'LL BE THAT.
IT'S DEFINITELY
A FANTASTIC PLACE.
WE APPRECIATE YOU.
THANK YOU, GUY.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪