HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
AND THE KICKER IS...
SOUFFLé PANCAKE.
ANYBODY ELSE
TRIPPIN' OUT ON THAT?
IN COLUMBIA, SOUTH CAROLINA...
IT'S LIKE PREMIUM BAR FOOD.
THE BURGER JOINT...
YOU CAN NEVER GET BORED
WITH A BURGER,
BECAUSE YOU'VE GOT
A NEW ONE TO TRY.
WHERE THE KICKER
IS DOING THEM...
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES--
REALLY GREAT TASTE TO IT.
SOUTHERN-STYLE.
MMM. THAT'S A GREAT BURGER.
IN BUFFALO...
OPEN BEEF UP.
THE LOCAL FAVORITE...
EVERYTHING HERE IS MADE
FROM SCRATCH.
SERVING LOCAL FAVORITES.
THE SOPHIA'S OMELET.
AND THE KICKER IS...
IT'S THE BEST!
HOMEMADE BREAD.
MMM! CAN YOU SMELL THAT?
AND IN BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA...
IT'S OLD-FASHIONED SERVICE
WITH GREAT FOOD.
A NEW JERSEY-STYLE DINER...
IT'S LIKE OLD DINER.
WHERE THEIR KICKER IS...
SNOUT.
NO.
EAR.
THEIR OWN TAKE
ON SCRAPPLE.
MMM. THIS, I REALLY DIG.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I'LL BE BACK FOR THE SCRAPPLE.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE ON HARDEN STREET
IN COLUMBIA, SOUTH CAROLINA,
BY THE FIVE POINTS AREA,
AND THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
THE MAIN DRAG
OF BARS AND RESTAURANTS
FOR THE UNIVERSITY
OF SOUTH CAROLINA.
NOW THERE'S ALL KINDS OF JOINTS
HERE JUST LIKE ANY COLLEGE TOWN,
BUT I'M HERE TO SEE ONE PLACE
IN PARTICULAR,
AND THAT'S PAWLEYS FRONT PORCH,
'CAUSE I HEAR THESE CATS
ARE DOING OUT-OF-BOUNDS BURGERS.
CAW CAW CREEK BURGER.
THEY GOT THE BEST BURGERS
IN TOWN.
IT'S AWESOME.
DONE MORE THAN A DOZEN WAYS.
YOU GOT
A SULLIVAN'S WALKING IN.
THAT'S HOW YOU SERVE IT,
WITH THE DAGGER IN IT?
YEP.
THE BEAUFORT--
FRIED EGG, APPLE-CURED BACON
AND ONION RINGS.
IT'S LIKE PREMIUM BAR FOOD.
THANKS TO CULINARY GRAD
KYLE TAYLOR.
BURGER TO GO.
I CAME UP WITH 99% OF THEM.
TRYING TO GET AS CREATIVE
AS POSSIBLE.
BUT THEY ALL START
THE SAME.
THEY GRIND
THEIR OWN MEAT HERE.
THREE BURGERS ON DECK.
THIS IS AS FRESH
AS IT GETS.
WHEN IT COMES DOWN TO IT,
WE COME FOR THE BEEF.
LET'S GRIND SOME BURGERS
AND SEE HOW THIS THING
ALL STARTS HERE AT PAWLEYS.
I GET THE WHOLE CHUCK--
CERTIFIED ANGUS BEEF.
TRIM OFF THE FAT,
CUT IT IN STRIPS.
RIGHT.
SO IT'LL FEED NICELY
INTO THE CHUTE.
YEP.
SEASON IT
WITH ROASTED GARLIC PEPPER.
SEASON IT NOW,
SO AS IT GRINDS, IT CONTINUES
TO BLEND IT THROUGH.
YEP.
SEA SALT AND THEN
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE.
EVERYBODY LIKES WORCESTERSHIRE
ON THEIR HAMBURGERS.
WHY NOT?
GONNA DO SOME MIX.
YEAH. THERE WE GO.
YOU GRIND THE MEAT
EVERY TIME YOU MAKE IT?
YEP.
I GRIND IT THROUGH TWICE.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
IF YOU'RE GONNA DO A BURGER,
CUT IT UP YOURSELF AND GRIND IT.
THIS IS GONNA GIVE YOU
THE GREATEST TASTE.
NOW WE TAKE THIS,
FORM 'EM BY HAND.
YEP.
WHAT SIZE PATTIES YOU MAKE?
8 OUNCE.
PRETTY GOOD AT THIS?
OH, YEAH. WANNA BET?
OKAY, LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE AT 9.
LET ME JUST JUMP IN THERE.
OOH. LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S NICE.
RIGHT ON THE MONEY.
I THINK THAT WORKS.
SO PUT IT IN HERE
AND FLATTEN IT OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO THE BURGERS
ARE DONE NOW.
WE LET THEM REST UP
FOR 24 HOURS.
AND THEN THE BURGER WE'RE GONNA
MAKE WITH THIS IS GONNA BE...
FRIPP ISLAND BURGER.
AND THIS BABY IS LOADED
WITH ALL KINDS OF FIXINGS.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
(man)
WITH THE BOURSIN CHEESE.
SOUTHERN SALSA.
REALLY HAS A GREAT TASTE
TO IT.
SOUTHERN SALSA--IT GOES
ON THE FRIPP ISLAND BURGER.
COWPEAS.
SOAK 'EM OVER NIGHT
WITH SALT AND BAY LEAVES.
GIVE 'EM A LITTLE BOIL
IN THE MORNING?
YEP.
BOIL.
PINEAPPLE, DICED JALAPEÑO,
SWEET ONION AND RED ONION,
SOME SCALLIONS, TOMATOES
AND THEN DICED PEPPERS.
SO EVERYBODY IN, AND THEN WHAT
ARE WE GONNA BIND THIS WITH?
CHAMPAGNE VINAIGRETTE.
CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR, GARLIC,
DIJON MUSTARD,
SALT, PEPPER, FRESH THYME,
FRESH OREGANO,
FRESH MARJORAM, FRESH BASIL,
WHOLE EGGS.
WE USE AN EMULSION BLENDER
AND SLOWLY POUR OLIVE OIL
AND CANOLA OIL
INTO THE DRESSING.
HERE WE GO.
BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
AND A NICE MIX, TOO.
IT'S NOT ALL BEAN WITH
SOME OTHER VEGGIES IN THERE.
YOU GUYS DID IT UP.
AND THEN SALT, WHITE PEPPER.
AND LET IT SIT UP FOR A DAY
OR SO.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
FRIED GREEN TOMATO--
I DIP THEM IN SEASONED FLOUR,
THEN A DIP IN EGG WASH,
THEN DIP IN SEASONED PANKO.
AND LET 'EM SET UP.
YEAH. HAMBURGER PATTY.
PUT IT ON THE GRILL.
YOU'RE GONNA WAIT TILL A LITTLE
JUICE FLOATS TO THE TOP,
AND THEN WE'LL FLIP IT?
YEAH. THEN WARM IT UP
ON THE FLATTOP.
DIG IT.
AND I'M GONNA GET A LITTLE
OF THIS BOURSIN CHEESE.
THAT'S A COMMERCIALLY MADE
CHEESE,
AND THIS IS YOUR RENDITION
OF IT, RIGHT?
YEAH.
AND WHAT'S IN THIS?
FIVE DIFFERENT TYPES
OF CHEESE--
THERE'S CREAM CHEESE,
PEPPER JACK, PARMESAN,
BLUE CHEESE AND GOAT CHEESE.
THAT'S WHERE THE TANG
IS COMING FROM.
I DID ACTUALLY TASTE IT
AHEAD OF TIME,
YOU KNOW,
JUST FOR SCIENTIFIC PURPOSES.
GREEN TOMATOES READY?
YEP.
SO THE BURGER'S DONE.
AND THEN...
LOOK AT THIS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO STEAM IT
THAT MUCH, BUT...
THAT CHEESE IS SO SOFT
AND THAT BURGER'S SO HOT.
OH, YEAH.
SO THE BUN--THE PRETZEL BUN--
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE
OF THE SOUTHERN SALSA
ON THE BOTTOM.
8 OUNCES OF BURGER
THAT YOU GRIND YOURSELF,
THE FRIED GREEN TOMATO
AND...
STAB IT.
YOU'RE GONNA GO
A LITTLE JASON ON US.
IT'S AS BIG AS MY HEAD.
MMM.
THE FRIED GREEN TOMATO
FITS IN THERE PERFECTLY.
A LITTLE BIT OF THE BITTERNESS
OF THE TOMATO
AND THE GREAT CRUNCH
FROM THE PANKO.
YEAH.
THAT CHEESE IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
LOOK HOW IT'S MELTED.
IT'S GOT THE SWEETNESS,
CREAMINESS.
A LITTLE SPINACH INSIDE OF IT.
THE BEAN SALAD IS GREAT.
AND THE PRETZEL BUN--
THAT'S JUST THE ICING.
THAT'S A GREAT BURGER.
THANK YOU.
SPICY, TANGY, SOUTHWESTERN
TASTE--IT'S TO DIE FOR.
THE FRIPP BURGER.
(man) I LOVE
THE FRIED GREEN TOMATO.
REALLY GREAT TASTE TO IT.
I LOVE THE FRIPP.
MAY BE MY NEW FAVORITE.
REALLY?
FRIPP!
YOU CAN NEVER GET BORED
WITH A BURGER,
BECAUSE YOU'VE GOT
A NEW ONE TO TRY.
MORE THAN A DOZEN
FAN FAVORITES...
PALMS BURGER.
LOVE THE PIMENTO CHEESE.
IT'S MY FAVORITE PART.
CAW CAW CREEK BURGER.
Y'ALL, THIS IS HUGE.
MMM!
WOW, DUDE.
JALAPEÑO PIMENTO CHEESE.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
IT ALL GOES TOGETHER GREAT.
THE MOST CHALLENGING PART
OF THIS JOB.
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
YOU CAN PUT ON A HAMBURGER.
BUT HE'S UP TO IT.
HERE'S YOUR SULLIVAN'S.
YEP, THE SULLIVAN,
NAMED AFTER
ANOTHER LOCAL ISLAND.
THERE'S PINEAPPLE,
SOME KIND
OF AWESOME MAYONNAISE.
"AWESOME MAYONNAISE."
YEAH.
AND THEIR
FULLY LOADED GUACAMOLE.
MAKE SOME GUAC?
YEP.
YOU GOT YOUR AVOCADOS.
YES.
SCALLIONS,
FRESH DICED JALAPEÑOS,
GARLIC, LIME JUICE AND THEN
I HAVE SOME CHIPOTLE SOUR CREAM.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF CHIPOTLES
AND ADOBO SAUCE,
GREEK YOGURT...
GREEK YOGURT.
AND SOUR CREAM.
HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE "S" AND "P."
MIX THAT ALL UP.
YEAH.
OKAY, TIME
TO MAKE THE BURGER.
BURGER PATTY.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUR BREAD.
IT'S A CIABATTA BUN.
LETTUCE, TOMATO, ONION.
A LOT OF GUACAMOLE
ON THE BOTTOM.
OKAY.
THE CITRUS
JALAPEÑO MAYONNAISE.
OH, SEE,
THAT'S NOT GONNA BE CREAMY,
JUICY, RUNNY ALL OVER ME.
UNH-UNH.
TOP THE BURGER WITH
THE PINEAPPLE, PEPPER JACK.
DON'T YOU COME BACK
NO MORE.
PUT A LITTLE WATER
AND LET IT STEAM UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
ANOTHER PETITE DIET BURGER.
LOOK AT ALL OF THAT
RUNNING OFF.
HERE ARE BURGER FALLS,
THE CASCADING JUICES
OF CHEESINESS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN THIS
"CUTTING BURGER IN HALF" STUFF.
I WANT YOU IN ON THIS.
I'M GONNA TEACH YOU
HOW TO EAT A BURGER LIKE THIS.
THIS IS THE HUNCH CARD. FIRST
IS YOUR STANCE. THERE YOU GO.
LET'S DO "GRAB & GRIP."
YOU GET UP THERE AND THEN
YOU GET THOSE ELBOWS OUT
SO IT DOESN'T RUN DOWN
YOUR SLEEVE INTO YOUR ARMPIT.
AND THEN YOU ROTATE IT UP.
I'M GUESSING YOU LEAN FORWARD
A LITTLE BIT.
MM-HMM. MMM! (laughs)
YEAH, HE'S A PRO.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT THIS,
THOUGH--
YOU DIDN'T GO TOO FAR
WITH THE GUACAMOLE.
THE PINEAPPLE
IS GRILLED GREAT.
THAT CITRUS MAYO
WITH THE JALAPEÑO
MAKES IT SUPER CREAMY,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
COME IN ON WEDNESDAYS
AND GET A FREE SCUBA SUIT
WHEN YOU EAT IT.
GREAT JOB, AND GOOD JOB
ON THE HUNCH.
THE SULLIVAN BURGER--AMAZING.
PROBABLY MY NEW FAVORITE.
BEST BURGER JOINT?
OH, BY FAR.
PAWLEYS PORCH BURGER,
CHEDDAR.
THE ONLY PLACE YOU HAVE TO COME
EAT WHEN YOU COME TO COLUMBIA.
BURGER TO GO.
I LIKE A BIG JUICY BURGER,
AND THAT'S WHAT THEY'VE GOT
HERE, AND IT'S AWESOME.
YOU NEED TO TRY ONE.
SOME PRETTY CREATIVE
STUFF ON THE MENU.
BURGERS IN THE WINDOW.
NOT JUST THE BLENDS,
BUT YOU MAKING THE ITEMS
THAT GO IN THE BLENDS.
YEAH.
OUTRAGEOUS.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
WE'RE HEADING NORTH
TO BUFFALO...
WE'RE GOOD TO GO THERE.
FOR--GET THIS--
A SALAD.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOT A BITE YOU SEE EVERY DAY
ON THE TRIPLE "D," RIGHT?
NICE BIG SALAD SHOT.
MMM!
I'M LIKE A RABBIT.
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
WE DIG ON TRIPLE "D"
IS STORIES ABOUT RESTAURANTS
BEING PASSED DOWN
FROM GENERATION TO GENERATION.
A LOT OF TIMES,
IT'S FATHER TO SON,
BUT EVERY ONCE IN WHILE,
WE GET ONE WITH A LITTLE TWIST,
LIKE A LOCATION HERE
IN BUFFALO, NEW YORK,
WHERE IT'S MOTHER TO SON,
WHERE SOPHIA ANANIADIAS
HAS RAISED HER SON SAM
IN THE BUSINESS.
NOW HE'S TAKEN OVER,
AND, BOY, IS SHE PROUD.
WELCOME TO SOPHIA'S.
OPEN BEEF UP.
HOW PROUD ARE YOU?
VERY. HE'S MY DIAMOND
IN THE SKY.
HERE'S THE SOPHIA'S OMELET.
HOW MUCH
DO YOU LOVE YOUR MOM?
OH, A LOT.
EVERYBODY AT THE COUNTER--
OH, MOM, I KNOW.
THOSE ARE STILL COMING.
CHICKEN'S DONE.
AND MY MIND'S STILL, YOU KNOW,
YOU COOK WITH LOVE,
AND THE PEOPLE ARE GONNA
LOVE YOU LIKE FAMILY.
MMM.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
ALMOST READY NOW.
ALL HOMEMADE AND FRESH.
FROM SERIOUS BREAKFAST...
CINNAMON APPLE
WALNUT PANCAKES.
THERE WE GO.
TO MOM'S GREEK HOME COOKING.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO THERE.
(Guy) THIS IS WHERE
YOU LEARNED TO COOK?
YEAH, I'VE BEEN HERE
ALL MY LIFE.
THEY'VE COMING UP NEXT.
HELPING OUT MOM
UNTIL SIX YEARS AGO
WHEN HE TOOK OVER.
THERE'S THAT.
I DO EVERYTHING HERE.
YOU HEARD HIM--EVERYTHING.
SO YOU GUYS
MAKE YOUR OWN BREAD?
YEAH.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT BREAD
WAS SUPPOSED TO TASTE LIKE
UNTIL I CAME TO SOPHIA'S.
WHAT KIND OF BREAD IS IT?
IT'S JUST A TRADITIONAL
WHITE BREAD.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN,
BROTHER.
WE'LL ADD SOME SALT.
YOU'RE NOT MEASURING IT?
NO, IT'S ALL EYE.
BAKING'S SUPPOSED TO BE
A PRECISE ACT, BROTHER.
YEAH, WELL, WHEN YOU COOK
WITH LOVE,
YOU KNOW, YOU ALWAYS ADD
A LITTLE MORE SUGAR THAN SALT.
ALL RIGHT, THERE WE GO.
THERE'S THAT.
A LITTLE YEAST.
SURE, SO YOU'RE GONNA EYEBALL
THIS WHOLE THING?
OH, YEAH.
(whistles)
YOU ADD THE WATER, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA START ADDING FLOUR.
DID WE AT LEAST
MEASURE THIS?
NO, WE USUALLY
TELL THE CONSISTENCY
WHEN IT STOPS STICKING
TO THE BOWL.
THAT'S HOW YOUR MOM
TAUGHT YOU HOW TO MAKE IT?
PRETTY MUCH, YEAH.
THAT'S REAL BAKING, MAN.
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA NEED
TO ADD A LITTLE BIT MORE.
IS IT A LITTLE SOUPY?
YEAH.
IS THIS
STARTING TO LOOK RIGHT?
YEAH, IT'S STARTING
TO LOOK A LOT BETTER.
WE'RE READY TO GET IT OUT
OF THE BOWL.
WE SET IT RIGHT UP ON TOP,
TIE IT UP, LET THE HEAT RISE IT.
SO WE'LL LET THIS PROOF.
OH, THIS THING LOOKS LIKE...
BALLOON READY TO POP.
GONNA TAKE THIS OFF.
WE'LL JUST PULL ENOUGH
TO START OFF WITH ONE PAN.
GONNA FLOUR IT A LITTLE BIT.
YOU'RE JUST ROLLING IT
INTO ITSELF.
YEAH, FOLDING IT OVER.
I MEAN,
VERY SLIGHTLY KNEADING IT.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO OVERWORK THE DOUGH.
NO.
BECAUSE THE YEAST MIGHT
JUST GET DESTROYED, YOU KNOW?
HERE WE GO. WE GOTTA OIL OUR PAN
SO THE BREAD DON'T STICK AT ALL.
POP IT IN THERE.
TWO LOAVES IN ONE PAN?
YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
LET IT RISE. SO NOW WE'RE UP,
WE'RE PUFFY. LOOKING GOOD.
YEP.
OVEN'S SET
AT SOME TEMPERATURE.
YEAH, HOT ENOUGH.
(laughs)
YOU JUST POP IT IN--
HALF-HOUR, 40 MINUTES.
AND THAT'S IT.
DONE?
YEAH. WE'RE READY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL. HERE WE GO.
THAT'S THE FINISHED LOAF.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET IT REST?
WE CAN CUT THAT RIGHT NOW.
YOU GET THE FRESHEST--
THE FRESH BREAD. GET 'ER GOING.
CUT IT.
STILL REALLY HOT,
YOU KNOW?
OH! DID YOU SEE THAT?
THE STEAMS
JUST AWES EVERYBODY.
OH!
YOU GOTTA BE REAL CAREFUL.
THAT'S AWESOME.
YEAH?
I MEAN,
IT WAS JUST BA-JAW.
I WANT TO BE HERE
EVERY DAY WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
SLICE ME OFF
A PIECE OF THIS.
ALL RIGHT. THERE WE GO.
MMM! CAN YOU SMELL THAT?
LOOK AT THAT!
NO DRAWN BUTTER.
WE WANT THE REAL THING.
MMM!
(mumbling) LOOK HOW THICK
THE CRUST IS!
DID YOU UNDERSTAND THAT
IN BREAD-INESE?
YEAH.
OH! BREAD'S FANTASTIC.
IT'S THE BEST BREAD IN TOWN,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
IT'S THE BEST!
AND A HECK OF A BASE
FOR THEIR
SIGNATURE SANDWICHES...
OPEN-FACE STEAK.
OH! IT'S HEAVEN.
AND THIS BUFFALO FAVORITE.
WITH THE CUT-FRIED BOLOGNA,
ONIONS ON THERE.
THAT'S--DID THAT HIT IT?
EVERYBODY HAS KIND OF LIKE
A COMBINATION.
FRIED BOLOGNA AND ONIONS--
YOU HAD ME THERE. GOOD TO GO?
HOMEMADE BREAD,
GRILLED ONIONS
AND ABOUT 400 POUNDS
OF BOLOGNA.
YES.
STACK IT UP REAL HIGH--
AND A LITTLE HIGHER.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
YEAH. PUT IT RIGHT ON TOP.
MUSTARD ON HERE. AND THAT'S IT.
YOU GUYS WANT TO COME DOWN
AND HELP ME EAT THIS.
HERE WE GO. MMM. IT'S GREAT.
THE BREAD'S MONEY. IT'S CRUNCHY.
IT'S LIKE YOU PUT BREADING
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE BREAD.
MMM! YOU'VE TAKEN SOME SIMPLE
COMFORT FOOD LIKE BOLOGNA--
THE FAT COOKS TO GET SOME
OF THE CARAMELIZATION...
THE ONIONS.
YEAH. I LIKE IT, MAN.
FLIP THE OMELETS.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS MADE FROM SCRATCH.
THERE'S THAT.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
HAVING A GOOD MEAL. GOOD.
THAT'S ALL SET.
JUST MAKE IT LIKE
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE.
AND THAT'S WHAT
YOU'VE TAUGHT SAM.
SO THAT'S ALMOST READY.
AND NO MATTER WHAT,
I'M GONNA MAKE IT RIGHT.
PICK UP ON
THE FIRST CHICKEN, PLEASE.
JUST THE WAY MOM TAUGHT HIM.
SPECIAL GREEK DISHES.
YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU HANDS DOWN.
I LIKE THE SOUVLAKI.
WHAT DOES SOUVLAKI MEAN?
MARINATED MEAT--
PORK, LAMB, BEEF, CHICKEN.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
REALLY?
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE MAKING
CHICKEN SOUVLAKI
TO GO ON TOP OF THE SALAD?
YEAH. START OFF
WITH SOME GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE SALT,
AND THERE'S THE BASIL, OREGANO.
AND SOME PARSLEY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD
THE OIL.
CHUGALUG, CHUGALUG.
THERE'S THAT. WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME LEMON JUICE.
NOT TOO MUCH, BECAUSE WE DON'T
WANT TO POACH THE CHICKEN.
NO.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GIVE IT
A LITTLE SHAKE.
AND NOW WE JUST ADD OUR CHICKEN.
JUST MIX IT UP A LITTLE.
SMELLS GREAT.
THANK YOU.
NOW HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA MARINATE THIS FOR?
FOR AT LEAST A DAY. TAKE USUALLY
ABOUT THREE TO FOUR PIECES,
DEPENDING ON THE SIZES,
GET IT NICE AND SEASONED.
AND ON THE SALAD--
ICEBERG LETTUCE,
TOMATOES, CUCUMBERS,
KALAMATAS, A LITTLE FETA...
YES.
RED ONION.
AND A LITTLE PARSLEY, AND WE'RE
READY TO ROCK 'N' ROLL HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
AND WE'RE ALL SET HERE.
LOOK AT THAT. WE'LL JUST
TRY IT BY ITSELF REAL QUICK.
SUPER TENDER, AND YOU GET
SOME REAL NICE CARAMELIZATION.
OKAY, IS THIS THE DRESSING?
YEAH. SHAKE--
A REAL GOOD SHAKE.
I MAKE THAT MYSELF, TOO.
MMM.
THAT'S GREAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOT A BITE YOU SEE EVERY DAY
ON TRIPLE "D," RIGHT?
A NICE BIG SALAD SHOT.
MMM!
REALLY, REALLY GOOD, MAN.
I'M LIKE A RABBIT.
(laughs)
(Sam) CHICKEN SOUVLAKI.
I LOVE IT.
I LOVE THE CHICKEN.
EXTRAORDINARY--
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
HERE'S A FRIED BOLOGNA
AND ONIONS
BY ITSELF WITH HOME FRIES.
AND THE REASON
I COME BACK
IS BECAUSE THERE'S LOVE
IN THE FOOD.
TWO OPEN BEEFS. I LOVE IT.
I CAN TELL YOU DO.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO?
TELL ME.
JUST CUT SOME PITAS.
SERVED WITH LOVE
IS ALL RIGHT BY ME.
WELL, THIS PLACE
IS, LIKE, FULL OF IT.
I'M GONNA GIVE HER MORE
ON THE SIDE.
DON'T MEET A LOT OF 27-YEAR-OLD
DUDES ACROSS THIS COUNTRY
THAT ARE REALLY GOOD COOKS,
GREAT CHEFS.
YOU GOT SOMETHING ELSE
GOING, MAN.
OH. THANK YOU, MAN.
I APPRECIATE IT.
YOU'RE A GEM, MAN.
NICE TO MEET YOU. AWESOME.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADING WEST
TO CALIFORNIA.
I'M PUTTING UP
THE SCRAPPLE.
OH, YEAH...
MMM!
JUST ANOTHER ORGANIC SCRAPPLE.
THE CRUNCH ON THIS
IS CRUNCH-TASTIC.
I'M FROM CALIFORNIA--
ACTUALLY SANTA ROSA
TO BE EXACT--
AND THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
THAT I DIG ABOUT FOOD
IN THIS STATE,
THINGS LIKE GRASS-FED BEEF
AND, YOU KNOW,
FREE-RANGE CHICKEN,
FRESH SEAFOOD, ORGANICS,
NATURAL INGREDIENTS.
I MEAN, YOU GET THE IDEA.
SO I GET ALL WOUND UP
WHEN I GET TO VISIT A DINER
THAT'S DOING ALL THIS.
I'M HERE
IN BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA,
TO CHECK OUT
BETTE'S OCEANVIEW DINER.
JENNA, YOUR FISH SANDWICHES
ARE UP.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
EXCUSE ME.
THE FOOD IS REALLY GOOD.
EVERYTHING'S PREPARED FRESH.
A LITTLE CORNED BEEF HASH
HOMEMADE--EXCELLENT.
IT'S LIKE OLD DINER.
READY TO GO.
I COME FROM NEW JERSEY,
AND I GREW UP IN DINERS.
SO WHEN BETTE KROENING
GOT A CHANCE
TO OPEN ONE IN BERKELEY...
WANT ANY MORE COFFEE THERE?
SHE KNEW WHAT TO DO.
BLACK-AND-WHITE FLOORS.
METAL TRIM.
IT'S OLD-FASHIONED SERVICE
WITH GREAT FOOD.
POTATO PANCAKES
ARE RIGHT HERE.
EVERYTHING FRESH,
EVERYTHING HOMEMADE.
RIGHT DOWN TO THIS
PHILADELPHIA FAVORITE...
SCRAPPLE IS READY.
USUALLY MADE OUT
OF PORK SCRAPS.
SNOUT.
NO.
EAR.
TONGUE.
NOT HERE.
I'M PUTTING UP THE SCRAPPLE.
WHERE BETTE'S USING
A LOT MORE THAN SCRAPS.
SO HOCKS
AND SOME PORK BUTT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
CUT THIS UP IN BIG PIECES.
AND THEN WE HAVE ONE ONION
AND THEN SOME CELERY.
WE'RE BASICALLY MAKING
A STOCK.
THE PORK BUTT
AND HOCKS
AND THEN PEPPERCORN,
BAY LEAF.
PEPPERCORN AND BAY LEAF.
FILL THIS UP WITH WATER,
LET IT SIMMER THREE HOURS.
YEAH. THAT'S RIGHT.
WHOA. THAT LOOKS LIKE
SOUPY SCRAPPLE.
SO WE'RE GONNA STRAIN THIS.
YOU WANT SOME HELP
WITH THAT?
YEAH, SURE.
AAH!
BUT LOOK OUT--SPLASHING.
REALLY?
BLUE SHIRT.
ALL RIGHT.
THE FOUNTAINS
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
THROW THREE COINS
IN THE PORK FOUNTAIN.
POUR THIS BACK
INTO THE POT.
WHAT HAPPENS HERE?
YOU PICK ALL THE BONES OUT.
PICK ALL THE BONES OUT.
AND YOU PICK SOME OF
THE CELERY OUT, SO YEAH.
GRIND IT UP A LITTLE BIT?
YES.
WE JUST SHRED IT
A TINY BIT.
WE'LL JUST KEEP WORKING IT
THROUGH IN BATCHES.
AND THEN ALL OF THIS IS GONNA
GET PUT BACK IN THE POT?
BACK IN THE POT
WITH THE BROTH.
BACK IN POT.
OKAY, ADD SALT
WITH CAYENNE.
SAGE.
SAGE AND PORK--
GOOD BUDDIES.
YEAH. BLACK PEPPER.
AND THEN WE SLOWLY MIX IN
SOME WHITE CORNMEAL
AND SOME YELLOW CORNMEAL.
POUR FASTER THAN THAT.
(laughs)
OKAY, AND THEN COMES
THE YELLOW.
REALLY GOTTA
STAY AFTER IT NOW.
STIR IT FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES
SO THAT IT REALLY
THICKENS AND THEN--
ABSORBS ALL THE MOISTURE?
JUST LIKE
WE'RE COOKING GRITS.
EXACTLY.
WE'RE TAKING OUR SCRAPPLE
FOR A WALK.
PUT IT DOWN HERE.
UP HERE?
YEAH.
UP THERE.
HERE IS GOOD.
SHE'S LIKE,
"DON'T MESS WITH ME, GUY."
REALLY.
DO YOU SLOP AND POUR?
I'M JUST GONNA SPOON IT IN.
LET 'EM COOL DOWN FIRST, THEN
YOU PUT THEM IN THE FRIDGE?
YES.
OKAY. THEN WHEN THEY'RE DONE,
THEY'LL POP OUT,
'CAUSE THERE'S SOME FAT
IN THERE.
YOU SLICE THEM, AND THEN
WE COOK IT ON THE FLATTOP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, LET'S DO THIS.
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
IT'S ALWAYS BETTER
WITH BUTTER.
TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
OKAY.
SO YOU GET A NICE CRISP
ON EACH SIDE OF IT, RIGHT?
YEAH. NOW TOMATOES.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER
ON THOSE?
YEAH, AND JUST LIGHTLY GRILLED
SO THEY SOFTEN A LITTLE BIT.
WE SERVE IT
WITH HOMEMADE APPLE SAUCE.
YOU GET TOAST, TOO.
I'M A SOURDOUGH FAN.
MMM! THAT LOOKS KILLER.
MMM!
IF THAT'S WHAT
SCRAPPLE TASTED LIKE
EVERYWHERE ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
I'D EAT SCRAPPLE FOR BREAKFAST.
THE CRUNCH ON THIS
IS CRUNCH-TASTIC.
THE TRIPLE "D"
SCRAPPLE SANDWICH.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM!
OH... MY... GOSH.
THIS, I REALLY DIG.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I'LL BE BACK FOR THE SCRAPPLE.
I GET THE SCRAPPLE
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
WE HAVE THREE HASH ALL DAY.
ALL RIGHTY.
EVERYTHING THAT THEY HAVE
ON THE MENU IS EXCELLENT.
VERY FRESH.
THE FARMERS COME TO US.
THERE'S THE TOMATO GUY BRAD
COMES--
BRAD THE TOMATO GUY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
DO YOU HAVE AN EGG MAN?
WE HAVE AN EGG MAN--
THE EGG MAN.
OH! FISHMONGER?
WE DO.
I BROUGHT SOME FISH
FOR YOU.
BRINGING IN
FRESH ROCK COD DAILY...
WHAT A BEAUTY.
FOR THIS TOP SELLER.
PAN-FRIED FISH SANDWICH.
DELICIOUS--
BEST FISH SANDWICH I'VE HAD.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
SALT, PEPPER, OLD BAY.
RIGHT.
WE'VE DREDGED THIS NOW
INTO A LITTLE...
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
THIS IS PAN-FRIED
WITH BUTTER
AND JUST SLAMMA-JAMMA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
(whistles)
AND IT'S GOT
TO BE REALLY HOT,
BECAUSE IT DOESN'T COOK
FOR LONG.
THAT'S GONNA GET SERVED
ON A BAGUETTE WITH
THE HOMEMADE TARTAR SAUCE
THAT'S MADE OUT
OF THE HOMEMADE MAYONNAISE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
'CAUSE THAT'S WHAT EVERYBODY
DOES--MAKE IT ALL...
YEAH. RIGHT.
FROM SCRATCH IN A DINER
IN BERKELEY. NO.
NO. YEAH.
TOASTED BAGUETTE.
AND THEN A LITTLE LETTUCE.
FRESH, DELICIOUS FISH,
AND THE TARTAR SAUCE,
AND THERE IT IS.
DO YOU THINK
I HAVE AN ANACONDA?
LIKE, DO YOU THINK
MY JAW'S GONNA SEPARATE
AND I'M GONNA--AAH!
YES.
SQUEEZE A LITTLE
FRESH LEMON JUICE ON TOP.
(exhales deeply)
(inhales sharply)
YOU DON'T TAKE
THE DEEP BREATH.
WAS THAT PRICELESS?
MMM. NOW THAT'S HOW
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO DO IT.
TASTE THE FISH.
A REALLY NICE
COMPLEMENTARY TARTER SAUCE
THAT DOESN'T STEAL
ALL THE THUNDER.
MMM. GREAT TEXTURE. LITTLE BIT
OF CRUNCH ON THE OUTSIDE OF IT.
SOMEONE SAYS, "I ATE A FRIED
FISH SANDWICH FOR LUNCH,"
THAT'S NOT WHAT YOU EXPECT
TO HEAR THAT THEY ATE.
RIGHT.
AWESOME. NICE JOB.
JENNA, YOUR FISH SANDWICHES
ARE UP.
CRISPY, IT'S FLAVORFUL.
TRADITIONAL WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF FLAIR.
EVEN WHEN IT COMES
TO THE BASICS.
WHAT IN THE WORLD?
IT'S AN APPLE BRANDY
SOUFFLé PANCAKE.
A BETTE'S FAVORITE...
I HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
HAVE YOU GUYS EVER SEEN THIS
SOUFFLé PANCAKE ANYWHERE?
PUTTING ON A SCRAPPLE.
AT BETTE'S OCEANVIEW DINER
IN BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA...
THE HUEVOS.
BETTE KROENING'S GOT HER OWN
TAKE ON DINER EVERYTHING...
YOUR SCRAPPLE.
FROM SCRAPPLE...
IT'S SO DELICIOUS,
I CAN'T RESIST.
TO CORNED BEEF HASH...
THEY MAKE IT REALLY CRISPY.
AND ALL KINDS OF PANCAKES--
POTATO...
BANANA GRIDDLES.
CLASSIC BUTTERMILK...
AMAZING.
AND GET A LOAD OF THIS ONE.
THE SOUFFLé PANCAKE--
FEELS LIKE I'M EATING A CLOUD.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOUFFLé PANCAKE BATTER.
SOUFFLé,
LIKE RISING SOUFFLé?
RISING SOUFFLé.
PANCAKE?
YES.
15 EGG YOLKS.
EASTER AT ROCKY'S HOUSE.
STIR THEM UP A LITTLE.
SUGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
HOW LONG
YOU'VE BEEN MAKING THESE?
27 YEARS OR SO.
SO SINCE YOU OPENED?
YES, SINCE THE FIRST DAY.
(whistles)
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD...
OH, I GOT THE BOWL.
OKAY. HALF-AND-HALF
TO LIGHTEN IT UP.
FLOUR.
I'M THE BOWL HOLDER.
(laughs)
I DON'T SEE
WHERE THE SOUFFLé PART IS.
WELL, THAT'S--
WHERE'S THE--WHERE'S
THE LEAVENING AGENT?
THE LEAVENING AGENT
IS EGG WHITES.
OH, SO YOU FOLD EGG WHITES
PER ORDER?
YES.
IT'S 6 OUNCES OF THIS BATTER,
AND THEN PUT IN THE BRANDY.
THAT'S A HEALTHY PORTION.
YES.
FOLD EGG WHITES INTO THAT.
LIGHTLY MIX IT UP
TO NOT BREAK IT...
RIGHT.
OR TO SQUISH IT.
SO NOW WE TAKE THIS VOLUMINOUS,
LIGHT, AIRY BATTER 'O' PANCAKE
AND FLATTOP IT?
NO, NOT FLATTOP IT,
PAN IT IN CLARIFIED BUTTER.
WHO CAME UP WITH THIS?
JUST GOT IT
OUT OF A MAGAZINE
AND STARTED MAKING THEM
FOR MY HUSBAND FOR BREAKFAST.
I HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
HUH.
ANYBODY ELSE
TRIPPIN' OUT ON THAT?
WE WAIT A MINUTE TILL
IT FIRMS UP A LITTLE BIT...
BEFORE WE PUT THE--
BEFORE YOU START
DROPPING THOSE IN.
YEAH, 'CAUSE OTHERWISE,
THEY DROP TO THE BOTTOM.
LET ME ASK YOU GUYS--
HAVE YOU GUYS EVER SEEN
THIS SOUFFLé PANCAKE
ANYWHERE?
KIND OF LIKE
A DUTCH BABY.
IT'S LIKE A DUTCH BABY?
OR A DUTCH BUNNY, YEAH.
DUTCH BUNNY.
YES.
I HAVE A DUTCH BABY.
I HAVE A DUTCH BUNNY.
DO I HAVE A DUTCH DOGGY?
DUTCH DOGGY, DUTCH BUNNY,
DUTCH BABY.
SO NOW I GOTTA PUT THIS
UP THERE IN THE HEAT.
OF COURSE YOU DO,
SO IT BROWNS THE TOP.
BROWN THE TOP, AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA FINISH IT IN THE OVEN
4 OR 5 MINUTES.
SO IT'S A 3-COOK PROCESS
FOR A PANCAKES-GONE-WILD.
YEAH, YOU COULD SAY THAT.
I DID SAY THAT.
HERE WE GO. AND VOILà.
HOLY GIANT EBELSKIVER.
GET ANGRY WITH IT, SISTER,
WHAT DID THAT SHAKER
DO TO YOU?
I'M A CRUNCHY JUNKIE,
SO I-I GET RIGHT AFTER
THESE TOP PIECES LIKE THAT.
MM-HMM. BUNCH OF FRESH BERRIES
IN THERE.
NOW SEE, THIS IS NICE
AND LIGHT AND AIRY.
THIS IS LIKE A PANCAKE
MEETS A LIGHT ENGLISH MUFFIN.
UH-HUH.
GOOD FLAVOR,
NICE TEXTURE ON THE TOP.
WE DO THEM WITH MANGOES
AND PINEAPPLE
AND RUM AND BANANA RUM,
APPLE BRANDY.
YOU HAD ME AT RUM.
SO I'M GONNA
PUT THE SOUFFLé UP.
THIS IS LIKE EATING A CAKE.
ALWAYS ROCKIN' FOOD.
THE FISH SANDWICH
IS READY.
THIS PLACE
IS LIKE THE CUT ABOVE.
HOW ARE YOU TWO DOING?
WE'RE PERFECT.
THE FOOD IS GREAT,
AND THE ATMOSPHERE IS GREAT.
IT'S JUST COMFORTABLE
TO BE HERE.
GREAT JOB.
THANKS.
GOTTA COME SEE THIS GIRL.
REALLY, SERIOUSLY, THIS
WAS AWESOME. I HAD A BLAST.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S UP?
ARE YOU TALKING
TO ME NOW?
NO, I'M JUST TRYING--
I'M TALKING TO THE KNIFE.
OH.
HEY, KNIFE,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?