HEY EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
THAT IS FLAVOR
ALL OVER THE BOARD.
WHO EMAILED ME
AND TOLD ME TO COME HERE?
WE ALL DID.
(Guy)
IN LAKEWOOD, OHIO
THE LOCAL FAVORITES...
IT'S THE BEST IN CLEVELAND,
I'M ALWAYS AMAZED.
(Guy)
THAT'S ALL ABOUT
A CHILDHOOD CLASSIC.
I THINK WE CAN STICK
ANYTHING INSIDE OF IT
AND IT'S STILL CONSIDERED
A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
(Guy)
AND THEY'RE DOING 'EM
MORE THAN 30 DIFFERENT WAYS.
OH MAN, OUT OF BOUNDS.
(Guy)
IN CHARLOTTE
THE LOCAL LEGEND...
I LOVE IT, IT'S GREAT.
(Guy)
WHERE FOLKS HAVE BEEN
DRIVING IN...
IT TASTES FRESH
AND IT'S REALLY, REALLY JUICY.
(Guy)
SINCE THE '50s.
IT'S GOOD, IT'S DELICIOUS,
IT'S TERRIFIC.
DID YOU GET THAT?
(Guy)
AND IN HOUSTON...
IT'S A LITTLE TASTE OF BRITAIN,
WE CAN GET OUR FISH AND CHIPS.
(Guy)
A PUB
SO AUTHENTICALLY ENGLISH,
HALF THE MENU'S INDIAN.
I DON'T PEOPLE KNOW
HOW MUCH INDIAN INFLUENCE
IN DISHES THERE ARE IN ENGLAND.
OH, IT'S HUGE.
(Guy)
AND WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS
OVER A LITTLE BASMATI.
AND SOME NAAN BREAD.
I WANT TO HAVE IT
AND I WANT TO HAVE IT NOW.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
I'M ALWAYS GETTING ASKED
ABOUT "TRIPLE-D" IS,
"GUY, HOW DO YOU FIND
ALL THESE CRAZY PLACES?"
WELL I TELL YOU, I'M NOT
THROWING DARTS AT A MAP
OR USING A OUIJA BOARD,
A LOT OF IT'S YOU GUYS.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW WHAT'S FUNKY,
YOU KNOW WHAT'S OUT THERE.
SO HERE I AM IN CLEVELAND
GOING TO ANOTHER ONE OF
YOUR FAVORITES,
MELT BAR AND GRILLED.
I NEED SOME CHEESE PLEASE.
YOU DON'T HEAR OF A PLACE
THAT JUST HAS GRILLED CHEESE.
TELL ME THIS PLACE
IS NOT OFF THE CHAIN.
DUDE, IT'S THE BOMB, MAN.
I'VE GOT A PURPLE PARMA
GOING UP.
WESTSIDE MONTE CRISTO,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S AMAZING,
THE FOOD'S REALLY GOOD
AND THERE ARE REALLY AWESOME
GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICHES.
IT'S THE BEST IN CLEVELAND,
I'M A BIG FAN.
(Guy)
SO IS MY AUNT POLLY.
THE CREATIVENESS
IS JUST AWESOME.
(Guy)
YEP, GRILLED CHEESE DONE
MORE THAN 30 DIFFERENT WAYS
BY CHEF AND OWNER MATT FISH
WHO JUST CAN'T GIVE UP
HIS CHILDHOOD FAVORITE.
I THINK WE CAN STICK
ANYTHING INSIDE OF IT
AND IT'S STILL CONSIDERED
A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
PEANUT BUTTER, BANANA,
CREAM CHEESE.
(server)
THE BLACKENED CHICKEN
FOR YOU, SIR.
WHEN I COME HERE
I ONLY GET THE BIG POPPER.
WE'VE GOT A BIG POPPER
HEADING OUR WAY.
KIND OF LIKE A JALAPENO POPPER,
JUST SANDWICH FORM.
TAKE IT FOR A TEST DRIVE,
MY FRIEND.
WOW, DUDE, THAT'S HOT,
THAT TASTES LIKE
A JALAPENO POPPER.
(Guy)
THERE'S EVEN ONE STUFFED
WITH THIS LOCAL FAVORITE.
THERE'S A GIANT POTATO PIEROGI
ON THERE.
THE PARMAGEDDON IS SO CLEVELAND.
WHY DOES IT GET CALLED
THE PARMAGEDDON?
THE FIRST SUBURB
OUTSIDE OF CLEVELAND
GOING SOUTH IS PARMA.
PARMA IS THE POLISH HOT BED
IN CLEVELAND
AND PIEROGIS
IS A MAIN STAPLE.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR GRILLED BREAD.
TURN OUR SAUTE PAN ON
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR VEGETABLE OIL.
WE'RE GONNA BROWN OUR PIEROGIS.
THEY'RE JUST FRESH POTATOES,
A GOOD HEARTY CHEDDAR CHEESE
IN THERE.
WE BROWN 'EM REAL NICE
ON BOTH SIDES.
WE ADD OUR GRILLED ONIONS.
NICE, SOFT CABBAGE FOR US.
THIS IS THE KRAUT SPICE
THAT WE MADE EARLIER TODAY.
VODKA, APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
AND THAT'S IT.
ALL WE'RE GONNA DO
IS LET THIS GET HAPPY,
HAPPY, HAPPY.
YOU ARE CRAZY.
I'M TELLING YOU,
MICHAEL SIMON,
ERIC AT MOMOCHO,
HEATHER AT LUCKY'S,
AND NOW THIS CAT,
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS TOWN.
CRAZY PEOPLE.
THIS IS GONNA REDUCE,
ALL THE LIQUID'S
GONNA BE GONE.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO FLIP THE BREAD?
PLEASE DO.
SOME SHARP CHEDDAR CHEESE,
BOTH SIDES OF THE BREAD.
WE DO APPROXIMATELY
FOUR OUNCES OF CHEESE
ON EVERY SANDWICH.
PIEROGIS DOWN FIRST.
THAT GOOD CARAMELIZATION
GOES ON TOP.
FLIPPIN' THAT BAD BOY
ONTO THE TRAY
AND INTO
THE MELTIFICATION MACHINE.
THREE TO FIVE MINUTES
IN THAT OVEN
TO GET THIS TO BE THE PERFECT
GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S DO THIS.
OH MAN, OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE CRUNCH ON THE BREAD,
FANTASTIC.
THE PIEROGI, GREAT.
BUT THE CABBAGE
WITH THE VODKA
AND THE CIDER
IT'S OVER THE TOP
AND AROUND AGAIN
OVER THE TOP.
THANK YOU.
THAT IS ONE OF THE BEST
GRILLED CHEESE I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU KNOW WHO I HAVE TO BRING
IN HERE?
AUNT POLLY,
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK OF THIS.
THAT'S THE BOMB.
BURSTING WITH FLAVOR.
IT'S BURSTING WITH FLAVOR.
(woman)
THE PIEROGIS WERE NEW TO ME
SO IT'S NICE TO HAVE THEM
IN A SANDWICH.
OUTSTANDING.
IT'S HARD TO DESCRIBE.
IT'S SO MUCH MORE
THAN A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
MY IDEA WAS TO TAKE A FOUR
OR FIVE-STAR RESTAURANT,
THAT QUALITY OF FOOD
THAT EVERYBODY'S USED TO.
(woman)
EVERYBODY LOVES GRILLED CHEESE
AND THEY JUST DO A LOT OF
DIFFERENT, NEAT THINGS TO IT.
(Guy)
LIKE HEY,
YOUR BASIC TUNA MELT.
NICE, BIG TUNA STEAK.
IT'S THE BEST WAY
TO DO A TUNA MELT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MARINADE FOR OUR
TUNA STEAK
FOR OUR TOKYO
TUNA MELT SANDWICH.
OKAY, GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
SOY SAUCE,
SESAME OIL'S GOING NEXT.
WHOA!
WHOA, BUDDY.
VEGETABLE OIL,
COCONUT MILK.
SO YOU'RE GOING
THAI ON ME NOW.
OH YEAH,
IT GETS BETTER.
BROWN SUGAR'S GOING IN NEXT.
SAMBAL CRUSHED RED PEPPERS,
BLACK PEPPER, CHOPPED GARLIC,
AND SOME WATER.
WE'RE JUST GONNA MIX
THE WHOLE THING UP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
OUR TUNA FOR 24 HOURS.
WE'RE TALKING SUSHI-GRADE
YELLOWFIN TUNA.
FOR A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH,
SOMETHING YOU SEE EVERY DAY.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE WASABI GINGER DRESSING
TO GO ON TOP OF THE TUNA STEAKS.
THE MAIN FOCUS FOR THE DRESSING
IS TOFU, MY FRIEND.
PICKLED GINGER
IS GOING IN NEXT.
A LITTLE COLD WATER.
TURN THIS BAD MACHINE ON
AND THIS IS ALL GONNA
COME TOGETHER PRETTY.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR WASABI POWDER,
JAPANESE HORSERADISH,
COLD WATER, WHISK IT TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR TOFU
AND OUR GINGER.
WE'VE GOT LEMON AND LIME ZEST.
SO A CREAMY SAUCE,
NOW A CHUNKY SAUCE.
A CHUNKY SAUCE.
WE'VE GOT FRESH ORANGE JUICE,
FRESH LIME JUICE, SESAME OIL.
YOU LOVE TO USE THAT.
YOU KNOW I DO.
DOUBLE BLACK SOY SAUCE,
RICE VINEGAR, FRESH GARLIC,
HONEY, KOSHER SALT,
CORIANDER, FRESH MINT.
I WANT TO GET SMOOTH AND CHUNKY.
AND THIS IS GONNA GO
INSIDE OF THE SANDWICH?
YES.
THIS IS OUR BEAUTY RIGHT HERE,
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT NICE
AND RARE FOR YOU.
WE'RE GONNA START OUR BREAD
WHILE WE'RE DOING THIS.
HERE'S THE THING
I WANT YOU TO LOOK AT.
HE BUTTERS ALL THE WAY
TO THE EDGE.
WE'RE GONNA TURN THIS GUY
AND MARK IT.
WE'RE GONNA FLIP OUR BREAD OVER.
IS THAT HERMAN?
THIS IS MUENSTER, MY FRIEND,
HERMAN MUENSTER.
FOUR SLICES.
OUR GINGER WASABI DRESSING,
SMOOTH AND CHUNKY.
OUR YELLOWFIN,
CLOSE HER UP.
THAT WILL GO INTO OUR
MELTIFICATION MACHINE
FOR 3 1/2 MINUTES.
(Matt)
THIS IS GONNA GET FINISHED
WITH FRESH TOMATOES
AND FRESH LETTUCE.
CLOSE IT BACK UP.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
A TOKYO TUNA MELT.
THIS IS COOKED
AT THE RIGHT TEMPERATURE,
REALLY RARE.
THE DRESSING WITH THE TOFU,
IT'S LIKE HEALTHY MAYONNAISE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE ALSO,
THE LETTUCE AND TOMATO THING --
THE CONTRAST
WITH THE COOL AND THE HOT.
THIS IS REALLY
A GOURMET PRODUCTION
INSIDE OF TWO PIECES OF BREAD.
YOU'RE MAKING SOME MAGIC, DUDE.
THANKS MAN.
TOKYO TUNA GOING UP.
IT'S GRILLED TO PERFECTION,
JUST A NICE CRUNCHINESS,
DYNAMITE.
YOU GET
THAT LITTLE HIT OF WASABI.
IT'S LIKE A SPICY TUNA ROLL,
BUT BETTER.
I'VE TRIED
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
AND I'M ALWAYS AMAZED.
HOW ABOUT BEEF JERKY
AND CORN MELTS?
WE COULD DO IT
BUT I DON'T THINK
IT WOULD SELL VERY WELL.
I'M TRYING TO SELL SANDWICHES,
I'M TRYING TO PAY BILLS.
OH, THIS IS A BUSINESS.
YEAH.
THERE'S SOMETHING HERE
FOR EVERYBODY.
WELL THANK YOU FOR
THE RECOMMENDATION AUNT POLLY.
BURN, PICK UP THE CHECK.
OKAY, WAIT HERE FOR ME,
IT'S IN THE MAIL.
(Guy)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING SOUTH
TO CHARLOTTE...
I LOVE THE CLASSIC
DRIVE-IN FOOD.
FOR A TASTE OF THE '50s.
PUT THE RINGS IN THE FLOUR.
GIVE 'EM LOVE,
TOSS 'EM, TURN 'EM.
YOU GUYS LOOK SO GOOD IN THERE,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE A GOOD DAY
TODAY.
SHAKE 'EM UP,
SHAKE 'EM UP, HELP ME.
WE'RE HERE IN CHARLOTTE,
NORTH CAROLINA TO CHECK OUT
A DRIVE-IN.
THAT SOUNDS FAMILIAR,
DOESN'T IT?
THE LAST TIME WE WERE HERE
WE WERE AT THE BAR-B-Q KING
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF TOWN.
WELL TODAY WE'RE AT
THEIR FRIEND'S PLACE,
AT A JOINT THAT'S BEEN OPEN
FOR MORE THAN HALF A CENTURY.
NOW IT WAS STARTED
BY THREE GREEK BROTHERS
AND STILL OWNED
BY THE SAME FAMILY
SERVING MORE THAN
20,000 MEALS A MONTH.
THIS IS SOUTH 21
SERVING CHARLOTTE SINCE 1955.
I WANT A CHEESEBURGER.
IT'S JUST AN INSTITUTION.
PEOPLE IN CHARLOTTE
KNOW IT AND LOVE IT.
IT LOOKS LIKE
YOUR KIND OF PLACE, RIGHT?
COOL CARS, COOL DRIVE-IN.
YOU WROTE AND TOLD ME
THAT I NEEDED TO COME
AND CHECK THIS JOINT OUT.
ABSOLUTELY.
BECAUSE...
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
IT'S TERRIFIC.
DID YOU GET THAT?
(woman)
I LOVE IT, IT'S GREAT,
CLASSIC DRIVE-IN FOOD.
I JUST GREW UP ON IT.
(Guy)
SO DID THE OWNER
MARIA HOUSIADAS.
HER DAD AND UNCLE
STARTED IT ALL BACK IN '55.
DID YOU ALWAYS WORK
IN THE DRIVE-IN?
EVER SINCE I WAS 14 YEARS OLD.
(Guy)
NOW SHE AND HER HUSBAND GEORGE
ARE KEEPING
THIS CHARLOTTE TRADITION ALIVE
FROM FRIED CHICKEN
TO ONION RINGS
AND THE BEST SELLER,
THE SUPER BOY --
A CLASSIC DOUBLE BURGER.
AND THEY DO IT
NORTH CAROLINA-STYLE
LOADED WITH SLAW
AND SCRATCH-MADE CHILI.
WHO'S CHILI RECIPE IS THIS?
MY FATHER HAD
THE ORIGINAL RECIPE.
I JUST MESSED WITH THE SPICES
A LITTLE BIT.
PUT A LITTLE OIL IN HERE,
GROUND ONIONS.
I THINK THE OIL'S HOT.
NOW THE MEAT GOES IN,
GROUND BEEF.
YOU'RE A DRIVE-IN
OWNED BY A GREEK FAMILY
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA HAVE
LIKE, ANY LAMB?
NO, THERE'S NO LAMB.
OKAY, SO WE COOK THE MEAT DOWN
AND NOW WE GO WITH THE SPICES?
SALT, CRACKED PEPPER,
PAPRIKA, A LITTLE GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, CHILI POWDER.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
CHILI POWDER IN IT
WHICH ISN'T FROM JUST A CHILE.
A LITTLE ALLSPICE.
WHICH ISN'T JUST
ALL THE SPICES,
IT'S A BERRY.
WE'LL FINISH IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA COOK?
ABOUT THREE HOURS.
TIME TO EAT IT?
YES.
MMM, IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT GOES OVER DOGS AND BURGERS.
RIGHT.
THAT'S THE FAMOUS SUPER BOY.
NOT FROZEN?
FRESH EVERY DAY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHEN IT'S TIME?
WHEN IT GETS WHITE
AROUND THE EDGES.
SEE, THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT BURGER.
LOOK AT THE CRUST
THAT IT BUILDS UP THERE.
PUT A LITTLE SALT ON IT, BUNS.
EVERY BURGER YOU COOK
GETS A LITTLE...
GETS TOASTED, YES,
TOP AND BOTTOM.
WE'LL FIX YOU ONE.
ALL RIGHT, DO IT UP BABY.
MUSTARD, ONION, SLAW,
AND WE MOVE OVER HERE
FOR YOUR CHILI.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT
THE CHILI ON THE...
CHILI ON HERE, OKAY?
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT.
YOU SURE IT'S SUPPOSED TO GO ON
THE VEGETABLES?
IT'LL GIVE IT
A LITTLE BETTER FLAVOR THAT WAY.
PICKLE, GO FOR IT.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT HAS ALL OF THE KEY PIECES
THAT A GREAT BURGER NEEDS
TO HAVE --
THE COOL SLAW,
THE BITE OF THE ONION,
AND THEN YOU GET THE CHILI
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
THAT IS BURGER 101 RIGHT THERE.
WE DROVE HERE BECAUSE OF
THE TASTE OF THE BURGER.
(woman)
IT TASTES FRESH
AND IT'S REALLY,
REALLY JUICY.
(man)
IT'S EXCELLENT,
JUST A GOOD BURGER.
BUT I CAN SEE WHY
YOU'VE BEEN SERVING
BURGERS SINCE '55.
WAS IT THIS WAY
BACK IN THE '60s?
OH YEAH.
(Guy)
FROM THE BURGERS TO THE DOG TO
THEIR TAKE ON A FISH SANDWICH.
FISH-O-BURGER.
IT'S SUPER MOIST.
IT'S GOT REALLY NICE,
BIG TEXTURE.
(Guy)
AND THIS ALL-TIME FAVORITE.
EVERYBODY COMES
FOR THE ONION RINGS.
SO 300 ORDERS OF
ONION RINGS A DAY?
NOW I'M
AN ONION RING AFICIONADO
AND I'VE BEEN CROWNED,
BESTOWED, LICENSED,
AND BLESSED
IN ALL FACETS OF ONION RING.
HOW DID YOU LIKE ALL OF
THOSE ONE-LINERS?
WHAT MAKES A GOOD ONION RING?
HAVING THEM CUT EVERY DAY.
BECAUSE ONIONS WILL DRY OUT,
THEY WILL LOSE THEIR PIZZAZZ.
AND ALL THE CENTERS
ARE PULLED OUT,
WE'RE JUST USING
THE NICE RING PIECES.
LET'S GET GOING ON IT.
1/2 GALLON OF MILK.
A COUPLE OF EGGS.
SALT, PEPPER.
WATER, REALLY,
THIS IS INTERESTING.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
THE BATTER HAS TO BE
A LITTLE BIT ON THE THICK SIDE.
DO YOU WANT ME TO ADD
SOME MORE FLOUR?
THAT LOOKS THICK ENOUGH.
START PUTTING 'EM IN THE MIX.
TURN THEM AROUND,
PUT THE RINGS IN THE FLOUR.
GIVE 'EM LOVE,
TOSS 'EM, TURN 'EM.
YOU GUYS LOOKS SO GOOD
IN THERE, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE A GOOD DAY TODAY.
SHAKE 'EM UP,
HELP ME, HELP ME.
I'M GIVING 'EM
ALL THE LOVE I'VE GOT.
SHAKE 'EM UP IN THE FLOUR,
THAT'S ALL THEY NEED.
NOW WE GO BACK OVER HERE
AND I DIP 'EM BACK IN HERE.
BECAUSE THE FLOUR'S
ON THE ONION RING
THE BATTER'S STUCK TO THE FLOUR
AND NOW IT ALL GOES IN
THE CRACKER MEAL,
WHICH IS A NON-SALTED
CRACKER MEAL.
I'M MINING FOR FOOD
IN FLAVORTOWN RIVER.
OH LOOK, IT'S AN ONION RING.
ALL RIGHT,
LET ME GET THEM OUT NOW.
WE DO NEED 'EM TO SIT AROUND
FOR THREE OR FOUR HOURS.
TO LET THAT BREADING COAT UP.
(Guy)
DO YOU WANT ME TO HOLD THAT,
NO, SHE'S GOT IT.
(Maria)
THEN YOU JUST PUMP 'EM OUT.
PUT ANOTHER BASKET
ON TOP OF 'EM?
YEAH.
YOU LET THEM GO
UNTIL THEY'RE GOLDEN BROWN.
ARE YOU GOING TO SALT THEM?
NO, THAT'S IT.
ALL WE DO NOW
IS PUT 'EM IN THE BOWL.
THAT'S A REGULAR ORDER?
MAYBE I ADDED AN EXTRA ONE,
YOU LOOK HUNGRY.
LET'S DO A CRACKING
AND A PULL.
YES, IT DIDN'T DRAG ALL OF
THE INNER ONION OUT OF
THE CRUST.
THAT'S A BIG DEAL.
MMM, REALLY NICE ONION.
THE BATTER'S NICE AND CRUNCHY.
YOU GOTTA PUT SALT ON,
A LITTLE KETCHUP.
JUST LIKE I SAID
ABOUT THE SUPER BOY
THAT RIGHT THERE
IS ONION RING 101.
MMM.
(server)
SUPER BOY ONION RINGS.
THEY'RE TO DIE FOR,
THE BEST I'VE HAD.
I CAN MAKE A MEAL
OFF THE ONION RINGS
THEY'RE SO GOOD.
AND IT'S WORTH DRIVING
150 MILES FOR 'EM?
ABSOLUTELY.
I LOVE IT,
THERE'S NONE OTHER LIKE IT.
THIS ISN'T FAST FOOD,
THIS IS HISTORY.
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT,
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
(Guy)
NEXT STOP WE'RE HEADING WEST
TO HOUSTON...
IT'S SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
(Guy)
FOR WHAT ELSE,
ENGLISH PUB GRUB.
I LIKE TO HAVE MY FOOD
TO HAVE A BEGINNING,
A MIDDLE, AND AN END.
DUDE, YOU'VE GOT MORE ACTS THERE
THAN SHAKESPEARE.
SO HERE I AM
BETWEEN THE MONTROUS
AND RIVER OAKS AREA OF
HOUSTON, TEXAS
RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM WHERE?
YOU'RE RIGHT, NIKO NIKO'S,
THAT GREAT GREEK JOINT
THAT I REALLY DUG
TO CHECK OUT THIS ENGLISH PUB
THAT'S DOING TRADITIONAL
ENGLISH FOOD
WHICH MIGHT BE,
WELL NOT EXACTLY
WHAT EVERYBODY'S THINKING IT IS.
I THOUGHT I WOULD CRUISE DOWN
IN THE RED '67 TO THE RED LION.
IT'S A LITTLE TASTE OF BRITAIN,
WE CAN GET OUR FISH AND CHIPS.
YOU CAN HAVE INDIAN FOOD,
IT'S FANTASTIC.
I DON'T THINK PEOPLE KNOW
HOW MUCH INDIAN INFLUENCE
IN DISHES THERE ARE IN ENGLAND.
OH, IT'S HUGE.
WE'RE ALSO GONNA GET
PUNJABI EGG ROLLS
AND SHEPHERD'S PIE.
(Guy)
SO WHEN OWNER CRAIG MALLINSON
LEFT ENGLAND
AND DECIDED TO OPEN
A REAL BRITISH PUB
HERE IN HOUSTON.
HE PUT HIS INDIAN FAVORITES...
AND ALL THE BRITISH CLASSICS
ON THE MENU.
IT'S VERY, VERY MUCH IN LINE
WITH THE PUBS IN ENGLAND.
I'M HAVING THE FISH AND CHIPS,
IT'S EXCELLENT.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS.
WHO EMAILED ME
AND TOLD ME TO COME HERE.
WE ALL DID.
THE BREAD PUDDING WAS AWESOME.
WHAT'S THE BEST THING
ON THE MENU?
CHICKEN TIKKA MASALA.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
FIRST OF ALL
I TAKE A CHICKEN BREAST
AND THEN I CUBE IT.
NOW I'VE GOT A MASALA.
YOU CAN BUY
PREPARED GARAM MASALA.
AND CUMIN, SALT,
WE HAVE GARLIC WITH GINGER.
AND THIS IS FENUGREEK?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S AN HERB YOU SEE
IN A LOT OF CURRIES.
WELL LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WATCH HIM KEEP ALL THE CHICKEN
IN THE BOWL.
SO THAT'S ALL MIXED UP.
BIG SHEET TRAY.
SO YOU THROW IT DOWN,
PRE-HEATED OVEN, 450,
FOR WHAT, 20 MINUTES?
25 MINUTES.
THIS IS OUR SAUCE
FOR OUR CHICKEN TIKKA MASALA.
OLIVE OIL, GARLIC WITH GINGER.
THEN I IMAGINE
YOU WANT THESE TWO.
CUMIN, GARAM MASALA.
NO, HOLD ONE SECOND,
HOLD ONE SECOND.
I JUST WANT TO
MIX THIS UP FIRST.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THIS.
TOMATO SAUCE.
BECAUSE YOU COULD BURN
THAT FENUGREEK, RIGHT?
UH-HUH.
I'M JUST GONNA POUR
HALF THE SAUCE IN
AND MIX THIS IN.
FENUGREEK.
I SWEAR,
IF THAT TOMATO SAUCE
IS ANYWHERE NEAR ME
I'VE GOT IT ON
EVERY PART OF MY BODY.
MORE TOMATO SAUCE, SUGAR,
AND WE HAVE SALT
AND TIME FOR THE CREAM.
A LOT OF CREAM,
THANK YOU.
YOU CAN MAKE THIS
INTO A BROADWAY PLAY.
THIS IS ONE OF THE ODDEST THINGS
WE'VE EVER DONE ON "TRIPLE-D."
THANK YOU.
AND I RESEMBLE THAT REMARK.
SO THIS IS GONNA COOK DOWN
AND TIGHTEN UP.
(Craig)
NOW WE'RE GONNA POUR IT OVER
OUR OVEN-FRIED CHICKEN.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT ALL THAT
IN THERE?
YEAH.
STICK IT IN THE COOLER
AND LET IT COOL DOWN OVERNIGHT
AND LET THE SAUCE
MARINATE IN THERE.
AND IT'S SPENT 24 HOURS TOGETHER
AND NOW WOULD YOU PLEASE
JUST COOK ME SOME OF IT TO EAT.
OH, OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS
OVER A LITTLE BASMATI.
AND SOME NAAN BREAD.
(Guy)
I WANT TO HAVE IT
AND I WANT TO HAVE IT NOW.
I CAN ARRANGE THAT.
(Craig)
FINISH IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE CILANTRO.
A LITTLE NAAN ON THE SIDE.
MMM, WOW MAN.
THE CHICKEN IS
MEGA SUPER TENDER.
THE SAUCE IS CREAMY,
NOT OVER-SEASONED.
DUDE, THAT'S SERIOUS.
JUST WHEN I THINK
I'VE HAD IT ALL...
IT'S DELICIOUS,
REALLY GOOD.
IF YOU HAVE A PINT
AND CHICKEN TIKKA MASALA
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE IN A PUB.
AN ENGLISH PUB
WITH THAT HOUSTON TWIST.
(Guy)
YEP, HOUSTON TWIST.
I AM HAVING
THE TANDOORI CHICKEN ENCHILADAS.
WE HAVE TEX-TANDOORI HERE.
RIGHT.
THE NAAN BREAD QUESADILLAS ROCK.
CHICKEN TANDOORI QUESADILLAS.
CHICKEN TANDOORI
QUESADILLAS, OKAY.
I'M GONNA BUTTERFLY OPEN.
SO YOU CAN GET
MORE OF THE SPICE ON IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
KOSHER SALT, CAYENNE PEPPER.
WE MAKE IT A LITTLE BIT HOTTER
HERE IN HOUSTON.
AND THEN THE REAL FLAVOR,
TANDOORI MASALA.
THIS IS WHAT YOU WOULD TYPICALLY
RUB ON CHICKEN WHEN YOU PUT IT
IN THE TANDOOR ON A SKEWER.
THEN I'M GONNA FLIP IT OVER,
AND GUESS WHAT?
YOU'RE GONNA PUT
PEANUT BUTTER ON IT.
YOU DO IT ALL OVER AGAIN,
ALTHOUGH PEANUT BUTTER GO NICE.
SO VERY LIBERAL
ON THE SPICE RUB.
WE PUT LEMON JUICE ON THAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA HIT THE OVEN
AT WHAT TEMP?
450.
THIS IS ONLY GONNA TAKE
MAYBE 25 MINUTES?
25 EXACTLY.
AND THEN WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT APART.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO HURRY UP.
NOW WHO'S KNIVES ARE OVER THERE?
JUST THE LINE'S,
I NEVER SAW THAT COMING.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
YOUR SHOW BEFORE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN...
THIS IS CRAZY GOOD,
I'D LIKE THAT
WITH SOME PASTA.
WE'RE GONNA BUILD
THE QUESADILLA.
LIQUID BUTTER, CILANTRO,
SUN-DRIED TOMATOES,
CHILI PEPPER.
LIKE THAT,
LIBERAL, LIBERAL, LIBERAL.
SOME SHREDDED MOZZ,
CHICKEN'S NUTS.
I'M ON MY NINTH PIECE.
WE HAVE THE PICKLED PEPPERS
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
MORE CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA PLACE IT
IN A FRY PAN TO SAUTE IT.
(Guy)
LOOK AT THE SPARKS,
IT'S LIKE FOURTH OF JULY.
YEAH, IT'S PRETTY COOL,
ISN'T IT?
WE PROBABLY CAN'T CELEBRATE
BECAUSE WE LOST.
THANKS FOR REMINDING ME OF
SUCH A PAINFUL EXPERIENCE.
OKAY, DOWN IT GOES.
FIVE MINUTES
IT'LL BE READY TO GO.
(Craig)
LOOK AT THAT.
HABANERO RELISH --
CARROTS, ONION, CUCUMBER,
GARLIC, AND, OF COURSE,
HABANEROS.
WE STEEP IT IN WHITE VINEGAR.
DON'T BE SHY, YOU'LL TASTE
THE CILANTRO, CUCUMBER,
AND MINT.
MMM, DELICIOUS, REALLY NICE.
THANK YOU.
THAT IS FLAVOR
ALL OVER THE BOARD.
I LIKE MY FOOD TO HAVE
A BEGINNING, A MIDDLE,
AND AN END.
DUDE, YOU'VE GOT MORE ACTS THERE
THAN SHAKESPEARE.
FIVE MINUTES
ON THE QUESADILLA.
(woman)
THEY'RE PHENOMENAL,
BEST QUESADILLAS I'VE EVER HAD.
THERE'S KIND OF SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE.
IT'S TRULY
A TRADITIONAL ENGLISH PUB.
(Guy)
AND THAT'S GOTTA MEAN...
SHEPHERD'S PIE,
JUST LIKE GRANDMA USED TO MAKE.
NO, MY GRANDMOTHER
NEVER MADE THIS.
(Guy)
WHEN WE COME BACK.
AT THE RED LION
IN HOUSTON, TEXAS
CRAIG MALLINSON'S DOING
THE BRITISH PUB GRUB THING
FOR REAL
FROM INDIAN FAVORITES
TO TRADITIONAL BRITISH CLASSICS.
(woman)
THIS IS THE BEST SHEPHERD'S PIE
I HAVE EVER HAD.
(Guy)
NOW SHEPHERD'S PIE
ALWAYS HAS LAMB?
LAST TIME I CHECKED
SHEPHERDS DO NOT SHEPHERD CATTLE
THEY SHEPHERD SHEEP.
THAT WAS THE PROBLEM.
TRIM ALL THE FAT OFF,
BREAK IT DOWN,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO,
CUBE IT?
NO, BIG SHANKS.
THE FAT AND THE BONE
WHEN WE'RE DONE WITH IT,
IT GOES IN A BIG STOCK POT
AND WE'LL MAKE OUR OWN STOCK
FROM SCRATCH AS WELL.
THAT'S AN IN DEPTH PROCESS.
I LIKE GOOD FOOD,
I LIKE FRESH FOOD.
(Craig)
A LIBERAL AMOUNT OF OIL,
FRESH GARLIC AND ROSEMARY.
YOU HAVE TO PUREE IT
'TIL IT BREAKS DOWN
REALLY EVENLY.
IT SMELLS SO GOOD.
YOU WANT TO HIT
THOSE ONIONS QUICK?
YES PLEASE.
KEEP THAT GARLIC FROM BURNING
AND NOW YOU WANT TO GO MEAT?
MEAT WILL BE GOOD.
NOW YOU'RE JUST GONNA PUT
A BROWN ON IT.
LOOKING LIKE THE MINCED MEAT
WE ALL KNOW AND LOVE.
DEEP BASE,
CARROTS, TURNIPS.
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE POTATOES ON TOP.
MY FAVORITE, CELERY.
WOULD YOU LIKE
THE BAY LEAF NOW TOO?
NO THANK YOU.
I LIKE THAT LAST
LIKE MY GRANDMOTHER SHOWED ME.
AND NOW WE'RE READY
FOR OUR STAR.
HOLY STOCK, BATMAN.
YOU WANT IT ALL THE WAY, CHEF?
ALL THE WAY.
HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA LET THIS
SIT HERE AND SIMMER DOWN?
AT LEAST 45 MINUTES.
OOH!
NOW WE'RE A KITCHEN.
BAY LEAVES, COOK IT DOWN,
LET IT COOL DOWN.
THEN LATER ON
WHEN IT'S SOLIDIFIED
AND IT COMES TOGETHER
WE'RE GONNA PLATE IT UP.
(Guy)
NO STARCH
TO TIGHTEN THAT UP AT ALL?
NOPE.
FRESH MASHED POTATOES.
YOU MAKE THE MASH YOURSELF?
ABSOLUTELY.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE BIT OF
CHEDDAR CHEESE ON TOP
AND IN THE OVEN,
FIVE TO SEVEN MINUTES
TO HEAT THE WHOLE THING THROUGH,
AND WE'RE JUST ABOUT READY.
LOOK AT THAT,
LOOK AT THAT STEAM
COME OFF OF THAT BAD BOY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
GONNA BE HOT?
MMM, THAT'S NICE.
JUST LIKE
GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
NO, MY GRANDMOTHER
NEVER MADE THIS.
THE AMOUNT OF GARLIC
AND THAT ROSEMARY KICKER
THAT YOU PUT IN THERE,
I GOTTA TELL YA,
I'M DIGGIN' IT.
THE VEGGIES ARE TENDER,
THE LAMB'S COOKED DOWN,
A GRAVY THAT IS JUST FORTIFIED
WITH MASSIVE FLAVOR.
A COLD DAY IN HOUSTON
I'D ORDER THAT LIKE THAT.
SHEPHERD'S PIE UP.
IT'S TASTY, VERY GOOD.
AMAZING, NEVER DISAPPOINTS.
YOU HONESTLY DON'T FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE IN HOUSTON ANYMORE.
THANKS FOR SENDING ME THE EMAIL,
BUT I GOTTA LET YOU KNOW,
YOU'VE JUST INVITED THE WORLD
TO COME TO YOUR QUAINT
LITTLE PLACE.
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT A PLEASURE MAN.
YOU ARE A FUNNY CAT,
YOU LOVE WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THE RED LION'S A KICKER,
I'M COMING BACK HERE TO PARTY.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
CAN I HAVE SOMEONE
VALET THAT CAR?
ABSOLUTELY,
GIVE ME THE KEYS.
SO I TOLD YOU
IF IT'S FUNKY WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
OH, A HOT ONION WENT BETWEEN
MY TOES AND MY FLIP-FLOP.
IT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."