HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
LOOK AT THAT.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
SHOULD HAVE MADE YOUR
"TASTE-A-VISION" SUBSCRIPTIONS.
STACKED, STUFFED AND LOADED.
IN
NARRAGANSETT, RHODE ISLAND...
A NEW SENSATION
FOR YOUR TASTE BUDS.
THE BURGER JOINT...
MOO-MOO MEDIUM.
WHERE THEY'RE BUILDIN'
BURGERS...
31 DIFFERENT BURGERS.
31.
AND PUTTIN' ON A SHOW.
POW!
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA...
TWO PULLED PORKS.
THIS IS GOOD.
A FAST FOOD FAVORITE...
FOOD'S JUST TREMENDOUS.
COOKIN' IT SLOW.
I DIDN'T REINVENT FAST FOOD.
ALL I DID
WAS JUST MAKE IT BETTER.
JUICY, DRIPPING GOODNESS.
AND IN ROSENBERG, TEXAS...
EVERYTHING MADE FROM SCRATCH.
THE FAMILY JOINT...
MA'AM, I CAN HELP YOU HERE.
STUFFIN' TACOS
BY THE HUNDREDS...
GUACAMOLE TACO.
AND DOING SOMETHING
CALLED A SNOBALL...
THERE YOU GO.
FOR NEARLY TWO DECADES.
HOW IS IT?
GOOD.
(mumbling) GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
EVERY OTHER YEAR,
THE FAMILY AND I VACAY HERE
IN RHODE ISLAND
DOWN AT THE BEACHES
WITH THE IN-LAWS.
NOW ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO,
WE RENTED A HOUSE
HERE IN NARRAGANSETT
ABOUT 2 BLOCKS THAT WAY.
NOW I MUST HAVE PASSED BY
THIS PLACE A HALF A DOZEN TIMES
EARLY IN THE MORNING,
AND FINALLY, I'M GONNA DO
WHAT I TELL YOU GUYS TO DO--
SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
IT'S TIME I CHECK OUT
CRAZY BURGER.
(man) FIRE BURGER.
THE HOMEMADE BURGER--
AWESOME.
MOO-MOO MEDIUM.
A NEW SENSATION
FOR YOUR TASTE BUDS.
(man)
CHICKEN MARSALA BURGER.
MY FAVORITE
IS THE GOOFY GORGONZOLA.
GOOFY GORGONZOLA BURGER.
MUSHROOM BURGER.
WHASSUPY BURGER COMING UP.
THE OWNER
HAS A CREATIVE FLAIR.
POW!
YA THINK?
WHEE!
BUT THIS IS SERIOUS STUFF
TO OWNER MICHAEL MAXON.
31 DIFFERENT BURGERS?
31.
ALL THESE
DIFFERENT KINDS OF MEATS,
DIFFERENT KINDS OF BREAD,
FUNKY SAUCES.
WHAT'S THE FIRST BURGER
WE'RE GONNA MAKE?
THE WHASSUPY BURGER.
WE HAVE YOUR 5 POUNDS
OF GRADE-A BEEF.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE RUB FOR IT.
THE ROASTED GARLIC,
SESAME OIL,
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
HORSERADISH,
BARBECUE SAUCE,
SOME GROUND ROASTED FENNEL,
CRUSHED RED PEPPERS,
CELERY SALT,
COARSE GROUND PEPPER.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
GRIND THIS UP.
(imitates blender)
YOU MADE YOUR OWN NOISE.
JUST IN CASE
IT WASN'T WORKING.
THEN WE'LL ADD IT TO THE BEEF,
MIX THIS ALL UP.
YOU REALLY
TRYING TO CONVINCE ME
THAT YOU DO THAT WITH
THAT SPATULA? THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW HOW I DO IT.
THIS GUYS GETS A FOOT
IN THERE, I BET.
OKAY, GONNA
PORTION 'EM OUT.
7 OUNCES, COVER 'EM UP,
HOLD 'EM IN THE COOLER,
AND THEN
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE WASABI MAYO.
CORRECT.
ADD A FEW LITTLE
CHIPOTLE FLAKES...
(makes popping sound)
TO THAT.
A LITTLE...
(clicks tongue, popping sound)
CAN I GET
THE CRAZY BURGER DICTIONARY?
WE'RE GONNA COME OUT
WITH THAT ONE.
THIS IS PREPARED WASABI,
STIR-FRY SAUCE.
THERE'S RICE VINEGAR.
MIX THIS ALL UP...
(singing gibberish)
WE'VE GOT THE BURGERS DONE.
WE GOT THE SAUCE DONE.
LET'S GO
COOK THE BURGER.
ALL RIGHT. WE ARE GOING
TO CHARBROIL IT.
PUT A LITTLE DIMPLE
IN THE TOP
TO KEEP IT
FROM GETTING TOO, UM...
TOO... (clicks tongue)
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
WE GOT A NICE WHOLE WHEAT BREAD.
BRUSH IT WITH BUTTER.
SLAP IT DOWN ON HERE.
FOR THIS BURGER,
WE MAKE FRESH ONION RINGS.
THESE ARE RED ONIONS
MARINATED WITH BUTTERMILK,
FLOUR, SALT AND PEPPER
AND THEN BREADCRUMBS.
OKAY, SO WE FRY THESE UP HERE.
SO NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
FLIP THIS ONE MORE TIME.
MELT SOME BRIE CHEESE.
I LIKE IT.
A LITTLE WATER.
THROW A LITTLE WATER
FOR STEAM.
OOH, WA WA. KA-CHOO.
(popping sound)
ALL RIGHT, I THINK WE GOT
THE MELTED BRIE.
WE'LL JUST PLACE IT
LOVINGLY ON THE BUN.
DO YOU WANT ME TO GET
THOSE ONION RINGS?
COULD YOU, PLEASE?
THERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT.
THOSE WILL GO
RIGHT OVER THE TOP.
A LITTLE BA-DA-CHOOM.
A LITTLE BA-DA-CHOOM?
THERE WE GO,
WITH THE SAUCE ON THE SIDE.
NOW THIS IS THE WASABI SAUCE
THAT WE MADE.
CORRECT.
THE WHOLE GRAIN BUN'S
REALLY NICE,
'CAUSE YOU NEED SOMETHING
THAT'S GOT SOME STRENGTH.
REALLY GOOD BURGER.
NICE ASIAN FLAVOR.
UH-OH, AND THEN THE BRIE.
TOTALLY WORKS.
LOOK AT THAT.
GOOD FLAVOR. OH, YEAH.
NOW I'M JUST GONNA GET A LITTLE
DIP ON THE WASABI MAYO.
THAT'S REALLY NICE. NOTHING
I WOULD CHANGE ON THAT BURGER.
NICE.
THE WHASSUPY BURGER.
PHENOMENAL.
MMM. WOW, THIS IS GREAT.
IT'S GOT A REALLY NICE
WASABI KICK TO IT.
THE ONIONS, THE CHEESE--
IT'S AMAZING.
IT'S UNLIKE ANYTHING
I'VE EVER HAD.
BUT DON'T LET THE NAME
FOOL YA.
'CAUSE IT'S NOT
JUST BURGERS.
THE FOOD
IS ABSOLUTELY EXCELLENT.
(Guy) WHAT'S SO GOOD
ABOUT IT?
YOU JUST KNOW YOU'RE GETTING
FRESH INGREDIENTS.
(Michael)
MAKING THE FOOD OURSELVES...
(man) THERE WE GO.
BRINGING OUT THE FLAVOR
IN THINGS.
LIKE THESE...
PACIFIC RIM ROLLS.
FILLED WITH FRESH
ROASTED CHICKEN
AND A GINGER-CILANTRO SLAW,
HAND-ROLLED AND DEEP-FRIED.
OHH! I'D LIKE TO ORDER 9,000
FOR A WEDDING.
AND THEIR FISH BURGER...
THE LUNA-SEA BURGER--
DELICIOUS.
TALK TO ME, GOOSE.
THE LUNA-SEA
BEGINS WITH SALMON.
CHECK FOR BONES.
TAKE THE SKIN OFF
IN ONE FELL SWOOP.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT UP
INTO GRINDER-SIZE PIECES.
YOU CHOP IT UP.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA GRIND IT.
GRINDING MAKES
A MUCH BETTER MOUTH FEEL
AT THE END PRODUCT.
REALLY?
SO WE BRING IT BACK,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MIX IT
WITH THE PISTACHIO PESTO.
PISTACHIO PESTO.
THIS FAR, WE HAVE BASIL,
ROASTED PISTACHIOS...
ROASTED GARLIC.
PARMESAN CHEESE,
A LITTLE ORANGE JUICE,
HOT SAUCE.
SO JUST SOME REGULAR
OLD HOT SAUCE.
AND WE'VE GOT
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
WHICH WE'RE GOING
TO THROW IN THE PESTO.
OKAY.
A LITTLE IN THE SALMON.
WHILE WE'RE PULSING,
WE'RE GOING TO LOOSEN THIS UP
WITH A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
SO WE WANT A LITTLE BIT
OF TEXTURE IN THAT?
WE WANT SOME CRUNCH.
I WANT TO TRY THIS.
ALL RIGHT,
TRY THE PESTO.
MMM. THAT COULD BE SERVED ON,
LIKE, A GRILLED FLIP-FLOP.
WE HAVE TO MIX IT
WITH THE SALMON,
THROW SOME BREADCRUMBS
IN HERE.
TO BIND IT.
SO NOW WE HAVE
THIS ALL MIXED UP.
THIS IS MIXED UP.
I MEAN,
(laughs)
SO NOW YOU
PORTION 'EM UP.
AND THEN
A LITTLE PRESS DOWN.
WE DON'T CARE
IF THEY'RE PERFECTLY ROUND.
OKAY, NOW WE GO
TO THE OVEN.
WE'RE GONNA POP 'EM
AT 500 DEGREES.
HOT AND FAST.
JUST BARELY COOK THEM.
THEN HIT RIGHT TO THE WALK-IN
AND COOL 'EM DOWN.
CA-CHING. WRAP IT
IN SOME PHYLLO DOUGH.
AND WE'RE GONNA...
(Italian accent)
GRISELE LE ATA COSAPONE.
YOU JUST
MADE THOSE WORDS UP.
(normal voice) YES.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A COUPLE
SHEETS OF PHYLLO DOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA FOLD THEM
NOT QUITE IN HALF.
FOLD IT NOT QUITE
IN HALF AGAIN.
AND NO BASTING IT
WITH ANY BUTTER?
WE USE GARLIC OIL.
PUT THAT BURGER
IN THE MIDDLE,
AND THEN WRAP AROUND IT
NICE AND TIGHT-Y WHITE-Y.
PLACE IT ON A TRAY TO COOK IT
FOR THE SECOND TIME.
500 AGAIN, ANOTHER 7 MINUTES,
TILL IT GETS BROWN.
PULL IT OUT,
COOL IT OFF QUICKLY.
HOW DO WE HEAT IT
FOR SERVICE?
PUT A LITTLE BUTTER
ON THE GRIDDLE,
THIS SIDE DOWN, PUT A LITTLE
BROWN ON THAT SIDE.
A LITTLE FLIPPY-FLIP.
JUST SO IT'S
COOKED THROUGH.
HERE WE GO. WE'RE GONNA
TURN IT OVER, CUT IT IN HALF,
MAKE IT LOOK PRETTY
ON THE PLATE. VOILà.
THAT GETS
THE ORANGE CHILI MAYONNAISE.
THE FLAVOR PROFILE
IS HUGE.
AND THE PISTACHIO--
THE CRUNCH AND THE TEXTURE
AND THE BITE THAT GIVES YOU--
GREAT.
YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING, MAN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I APPRECIATE IT.
YOU REALLY KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
LUNA-SEA BURGER.
DELICATELY SEASONED,
AND WITH THE SAUCE--
IT'S GREAT.
GOOD TEXTURE. IT'S CRUNCHY,
AND IT'S, LIKE, LIGHT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
FOUR, FIVE, SIX,
SEVEN BURGERS.
THIS PLACE IS GREAT.
FREAKY FAJITA BURGER.
EVERYTHING'S DIFFERENT.
YOU COULD DO BREAKFAST,
LUNCH, DINNER, DESSERT,
REALLY,
ANYTHING IN BETWEEN.
NICE JOB.
I GIVE THIS
A "WA WA WA WA WA!"
AHH. THAT'S BETTER THAN A...
(speaking gibberish)
THAT YOU GAVE IT BEFORE.
UP NEXT...
OINKSTER PASTRAMI COMBO.
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA...
AMAZING.
FOR FAST FOOD...
LIQUA-SMOKA-
PORKA-FLAVOR.
DONE SLOW.
DEFINITELY SLOW-COOKING IT
IN THAT PEPPER
JUST MAKES A HUGE DIFFERENCE.
IF YOU LOVE PASTRAMI,
YOU WOULD FLIP OVER THIS.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S A LOT
OF REALLY HOT TOPICS
GOING ON IN FOOD RIGHT NOW,
AND ONE OF THEM
IS FAST FOOD OR NOT.
NOW MY POSITION IS THIS--
QUALITY, NOT QUANTITY,
HANDMADE, NOT OVERPROCESSED.
AND FROM I AM HEARIN',
THE OINKSTER
IN EAGLE ROCK, CALIFORNIA,
IS JUST THAT.
(man) COMBO.
AMAZING.
TWO PULLED PORKS.
NICE. THANKS.
THIS IS GOOD.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG
IF THE PLACE IS CALLED OINKSTER.
THE FOOD'S TREMENDOUS.
THERE'S DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
THIS IS
ALL-AMERICAN PASTRAMI
AND BURGERS
AND CHILI AND FRIES.
THEY KIND OF PUT
A CLASSIER TWIST ON IT.
THANKS TO FORMER FINE DINING
CHEF ANDRE GUERRERO.
I DIDN'T REINVENT FAST FOOD.
ALL I DID
WAS JUST MAKE IT BETTER.
HALF CHICKEN WITH FRIES.
LIKE SLOW-COOKIN' THE BIRDS
FOR A CHICKEN SALAD SANDWICH...
BEAUTIFUL.
BRINING AND SMOKING
PULLED PORK
AND CRANKING OUT 1,500 POUNDS
OF PASTRAMI A WEEK.
OINKSTER PASTRAMI COMBO.
YOU PEPPER IT, AND YOU SMOKE IT,
AND THIS IS THE MIXTURE.
NOW IS THIS FRESH GROUND BLACK?
IT SMELLS LIKE IT.
YEAH, FRESH GROUND PEPPER
AND CORIANDER.
GIVE IT A NICE COATING.
THAT IS AWESOME.
HIT THE SMOKER AT 240
FOR ABOUT 4 HOURS, AND VOILà.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
LET'S PULL THIS OUT.
(whistles) COME HERE
AND CHECK THIS OUT.
LOOK AT THE JUICES
JUST FLOWING.
WATCH THIS.
NOW YOU TYPICALLY LET THIS REST
WHEN YOU PULL IT OUT, CORRECT?
OH, YEAH.
OHH! SOP UP SOME OF THAT.
YOU KNOW, I DO THIS
JUST FOR YOU GUYS.
THAT IS KILLER. THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT RIGHT THERE.
JUICY, DRIPPING GOODNESS.
DON'T CUT ANY MORE.
JUST GET THAT IN THE CAR.
YEAH, DEFINITELY SLOW-COOKING IT
IN THAT PEPPER
JUST MAKES A HUGE DIFFERENCE.
YOU PUT IN ON SANDWICHES.
YOU PUT IN ON BURGERS...
(Andre) I'M GONNA
NEED FRIES WITH THAT.
AND THE OINKSTER PASTRAMI--
THE SANDWICH
THEY NAMED AFTER THE PLACE.
THE OINKSTER PASTRAMI
IS QUITE AMAZING.
THAT IS THE SANDWICH.
TOASTED FRENCH BREAD,
A NICE BIG PILE
OF PASTRAMI.
WHOA!
THIS IS MORE
OF A FRENCH DIP STYLE.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
GRUYèRE CHEESE
AND THEN SOME
OF OUR RED COLESLAW.
(whistles)
AND THEN THE PASADENA HIGH
FOOTBALL TEAM'S
GONNA COME OVER
AND EAT IT WITH ME.
IF YOU LOVE PASTRAMI,
YOU WOULD FLIP OVER THIS.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE ONIONS,
THE SOURNESS OF THE SLAW--
MMM--FORTIFIED WITH SOME
REAL RICH GRUYèRE CHEESE...
THANK YOU.
AND THAT PASTRAMI
RUBBED AND SMOKED--
GET OUT OF HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
SHOULD HAVE MADE YOUR
"TASTE-A-VISION" SUBSCRIPTIONS.
FANTASTIC. YOU KNOW,
I TRY TO GET OTHER THINGS,
BUT EVERY TIME I COME,
I HAVE TO GET THAT.
GREAT EATIN', MAN.
IT'S GREAT FOOD.
GOT A REUBEN
AND A CHICKEN SALAD SANDWICH.
AND THE FOOD IS REALLY SIMPLE,
VERY STRAIGHTFORWARD,
MAKING EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH.
BELGIAN FRIES.
THE FRIES ARE TWICE COOKED,
SO THEY'RE CRISPY.
(crunches)
YOU CAN HEAR IT.
MMM, THAT'S A GREAT FRY.
YOU CAN'T HAVE THEM
WITHOUT THE GARLIC AIOLI.
IT'S ACTUALLY REQUIRED.
MMM. MAN,
THE AIOLI GOES FOR IT.
SALTY, CRUNCHY GOODNESS.
NO KETCHUP
FOR THESE GUYS, HUH?
NO, NO.
BUT HE'S SCRATCH-MAKING THAT,
TOO.
YOU MAKE YOUR MUSTARD,
YOU MAKE YOUR CHIPOTLE KETCHUP,
REGULAR MUSTARD
AND A HOUSE KETCHUP.
YEAH,
AND WE MAKE ALL OF IT.
I WANT TO STASH AWAY SOME OF
THAT MUSTARD AND BRING IT HOME.
(Andre) PIGGY FRIES,
BEET SALAD FOR JEREMY.
(man) BEAUTIFUL.
THE CONCEPT--
THE SLOW FAST FOOD...
(man) IT'S NOT SLOW
WHEN YOU ORDER IT,
BUT IT'S DEFINITELY SLOW
WHEN THEY COOK IT,
WHICH IS THE ONLY WAY
TO MAKE PASTRAMI,
THE ONLY WAY
TO COOK GOOD PULLED PORK.
I COME HERE SPECIFICALLY
FOR THE PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
THEN I GO IN WITH
THE CAROLINA BARBECUE SAUCE.
ALSO HOMEMADE.
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
UH, THIS IS MINE.
IT'S A VINEGAR-BASED
SAUCE.
WHERE ARE WE STARTING?
IN HERE, SUGAR FIRST,
SALT...
OKAY.
BLACK PEPPER
AND OUR CHILIES.
THAT'S A HEALTHY AMOUNT
OF CHILI. I LIKE IT.
HEY, I GOTTA HAVE
A LITTLE HEAT IN THERE.
AND THEN WE PUT THE WATER,
AND WE GOT
SOME CIDER VINEGAR HERE.
A LITTLE DRY MUSTARD.
SOME DRY MUSTARD
RIGHT HERE.
I KNOW.
I JUST GAVE IT TO YA.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
SOY SAUCE--
THEY USE A LOT OF THIS
IN THE CAROLINAS--
A LITTLE MOLASSES HERE,
TOMATO PASTE.
THIS IS KETCHUP.
THIS IS THE KETCHUP
YOU GUYS MAKE?
YEAH.
WOW.
BRING IT TO A BOIL,
AND THEN SHUT HER DOWN...
AND THAT'S IT.
AND SHE'S GOOD TO GO.
GIVE IT ENOUGH TIME
FOR THOSE CHILIES TO STEEP
IN THAT VINEGAR.
AND THIS WILL GO
ON THE PULLED PORK SANDWICH?
YEAH.
YOU BRINE YOUR PORK BUTTS.
SO WE START OUT
WITH WATER,
SOME SALT--PUT THAT
RIGHT IN THERE--
SUGAR--THE SWEETNESS JUST
GIVES IT A LITTLE BALANCE--
SOME HONEY...
OR "HOON-AY."
MOLASSES,
AND THIS IS A SOY SAUCE.
WOW. I LIKE THE WAY YOU PLAY.
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
HIT IT IN THE ICE WATER.
LET IT COOL DOWN.
OTHERWISE, WE'D SIT THERE
AND POACH IT.
NOW IT'S ONTO
THE PORK BUTT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
PUT SOME HOLES IN THIS,
LET THE BRINE
PENETRATE REALLY WELL.
OH, YOU'LL GET
PENETRATION NOW.
THIS IS GONNA SIT
FOR TWO DAYS.
HOW MANY CASES ARE YOU
GOING THROUGH A WEEK?
GOING THROUGH
10 TO 12 CASES A WEEK.
80 TO 100 BUTTS? WOW.
WE'VE GOT ONE
THAT'S READY TO ROCK.
OUR RUB IS JUST
SALT AND PEPPER.
YOU GOT THE SUGAR ALREADY
GOING IN THE BRINE.
WHEN YOU'VE GOT A LOT
OF FLAVOR IN THE BRINE,
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED.
MAN, THAT IS A GENTLE AMOUNT
OF RUB, MY FRIEND.
WE'RE GONNA
LOAD UP THE SMOKER.
WE SMOKE 'EM OVERNIGHT--
210, 220.
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
I GOT IT. SAME TEAM,
SAME TEAM. GO!
CATCH AND RELEASE.
IT LOOKS GREAT.
IT DEFINITELY FALLS APART.
CHOP IT UP.
HUH, I SEE WHY YOU JUST DID
THE RUB WITH SALT AND PEPPER.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE SALTINESS
TO IT, A LITTLE KICK.
YOU MIX SOME OF THAT
CRUSTY BARK ON THE OUTSIDE
WITH THE INSIDE
WHERE IT'S NICE AND TENDER,
OR YOU JUST SIT HERE
AND PICK AT IT LIKE I WILL.
WE SAVE ALL THE DRIPPINGS
AND LADLE OUT THE FAT,
AND THEN WE PUT SOME
OF THE JUICES RIGHT BACK IN.
SO THAT'S JUST LIKE
LIQUA-SMOKA-PORKA-FLAVOR.
YOU CAN QUOTE ME ON THAT.
YEAH, EXACTLY. I'M GONNA
PUT THAT ON MY MENU.
I WOULD...
(bell tinkles)
GOT IT?
I LOVE IT.
(bell dinging)
WE SERVE IT
ON A FRENCH ROLL,
CARAMELIZED ONION ON THERE
AND OUR BARBECUE SAUCE
AND THEN SOME
OF OUR RED COLESLAW.
(whistles)
MMM.
THAT'S REALLY ON POINT.
THAT PORK REALLY HAS
A UNIQUE STYLE--VERY RICH
WITH THAT SOY AND THE MOLASSES
AND THE HONEY.
THEN VINEGAR
PLAYS INTO IT.
THAT BARBECUE SAUCE IS GREAT.
REALLY NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
IT'S AMAZING. THIS IS ACTUALLY
THE ONLY THING I'VE EVER TRIED,
AND I'VE NEVER WANTED
TO TRY ANYTHING ELSE.
THIS IS MY PLACE FOR PULLED
PORK. IT'S A GOOD SANDWICH.
THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE LIKE IT.
(Andre) QUARTER CHICKEN,
FRIES AND PLANTAINS.
ARE YOU HAPPY
WITH YOUR RESULT?
YEAH, I LOVE THIS PLACE.
WHEN YOU FIND SOMETHING
THAT GOOD, YOU STICK WITH IT.
AWESOME JOB, MAN.
AWESOME.
NEXT STOP...
(woman)
CHICKEN TACO SALAD.
WE'RE HEADIN'
SOUTH OF HOUSTON...
I LOVE TO COME HERE EVERY DAY.
FOR TACOS...
DROP THE BALL IN, AND IT SHOOTS
THEM OUT ON THE FLATTOP.
THAT SCORE.
OHH! HE SHOOTS, HE SCORES.
SO THE OTHER DAY,
SOMEBODY ASKED ME,
"HEY, GUY,
YOU EVER THINK YOU'LL RUN OUT
"OF DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES
TO CHECK OUT?
I MEAN, YOU THINK EVER THE FUNKY
JOINTS WILL BECOME EXTINCT?"
I SAID, "THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE."
ALL YOU GOTTA DO IS SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND,
LIKE HERE IN ROSENBERG, TEXAS,
30 MILES SOUTHWEST OF HOUSTON,
WHERE AN ABANDONED GAS STATION
HAS MORPHED INTO BOB'S
TACO STATION AND SNOBALLS.
ONE SMALL STRAWBERRY.
A STRAWBERRY SNOBALL
IS WONDERFUL.
AND THAT'S A SNOBALL...
THIS IS DIFFERENT
THAN A SNOW CONE.
THE ICE TASTES POWDERY.
YEAH, IT'S SHAVED MORE.
A LITTLE BIG OF MAGIC.
THAT BOB ALANIS STARTED SERVING
IN THE SUMMER OF '91.
SMALL CHERRY.
IT WAS A HUGE HIT...
DOUBLE TIGER'S BLOOD.
TILL SUMMER ENDED...
HERE YOU GO,
LITTLE LADY.
SO HIS MOM SAID,
"WE'LL EXPAND THE MENU"...
(woman) TWO CRISPY TACOS.
TO THE TACOS WE MAKE AT HOME.
I SAID, "OKAY,
LET'S GIVE IT A SHOT."
18 YEARS LATER, THEY'RE SERVIN'
ALL KINDS OF TACOS.
GUACAMOLE TACO.
(man) BARBACOA TACO.
ONE CHICHARRON.
EVERYTHING MADE FROM SCRATCH.
EVEN THE TORTILLAS
THAT BOB'S NEPHEW PACO'S
BEEN ROLLING OUT FOR YEARS.
TORTILLAS.
YOU ADD THE FLOUR,
SALT, BAKING POWDER.
MANTECA, WHICH IS...
THE LARD.
DON'T TEASE ME WITH ANY OF THAT
VEGETABLE SHORTENING.
WE'VE TRIED IT WITH VEGETABLE
SHORTENING. UNH-UNH.
UNH-UNH ON THAT ONE.
OKAY.
WATER. AND THEN JUST LET IT MIX
JUST IT COMES TOGETHER.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
I JUST MAKE DOUGH BALLS.
SO HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU MAKE A DAY?
WE MAKE ABOUT 2,000
TORTILLAS A DAY.
SOMEONE DOES... (mumbles)
2,000 TIMES?
YES.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT 'EM
IN OUR TORTILLA PRESS.
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
WE DUST 'EM GENEROUSLY,
DROP THE BALL IN, AND IT SHOOTS
THEM OUT ON THE FLATTOP.
READY? AND... NOW.
OHH!
HE SHOOTS, HE SCORES.
THAT IS AWESOME.
IT'S LIKE TORTILLA AIR HOCKEY.
(imitates honking)
SO THESE BUBBLE A LITTLE BIT,
AND YOU FLIP 'EM,
AND THEN YOU JUST
TAKE 'EM OFF.
THAT'S AWESOME.
FRESH, HOT.
WHAT TACO
DO YOU RECOMMEND WE TRY?
CARNE GUISADA.
SO WE'VE GOT SOME
CUBED BLADE MEAT.
AND NO OIL?
NO OIL, NO.
JUST SEAR IT.
JUST PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE?
YES. COVER IT WITH WATER. WE
WANT IT TO GET SOFT AND TENDER.
ONCE THAT SIMMERS,
YOU ADD THE RED PEPPERS,
ONION, GREEN BELL PEPPER
AND TOMATO.
YOU LET THAT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
THE SPICE MIX
FOR THE CARNE GUISADA.
SO WE ADD WHOLE GARLIC,
CUMIN SEED.
NOW BEING THE CULINARIAN,
YOU DON'T TOAST THAT
AHEAD OF TIME?
I'VE TRIED IT TOASTED.
MY GRANDMA DIDN'T LIKE IT.
REALLY?
SHE SAID IT WAS TOO SMOKY.
SO WE HAVE CHICKEN STOCK
WITH TOMATO BOUILLON,
BLACK PEPPER
AND CRUSHED TOMATO.
A LITTLE WATER.
ALL PURéED TOGETHER.
THIS IS GONNA GO FOR OUR BEEF.
YES.
AND THIS IS REALLY GONNA BE
KIND OF LIKE THE BASE OF THIS.
THE BASE, YEAH.
ANYTHING ELSE
WE'RE GONNA ADD TO IT.
YES, A BLONDE ROUX.
BLONDE ROUX IS...
MANTECA AND FLOUR.
AND A LITTLE MORE
HEAT ON THAT
UNTIL THAT STARTS
TO DO ITS THICKENING.
AND THEN IT'S DONE.
WE PUT TWO SCOOPS
ON A TACO.
TWO SCOOPS?
YEAH, WE FILL 'EM UP.
AND YOU CAN ADD CHEESE.
A LITTLE SALSA.
IS THIS SUPER HOT?
NO, IT'S MILD.
THE MEAT--SUPER TENDER.
GOT SOME CREAMINESS TO IT.
I LOVE SEEING THE PEPPERS
INSIDE OF IT.
BUT THE NAPALM GRAVY IS HOT--
THE LAVA.
IS THAT
WHAT YOU GUYS CALL IT?
YEAH.
A TON OF PEOPLE ARE MAKING CORN,
BUT THE FLOUR IS THE WAY TO GO.
NICE JOB.
THANKS, BROTHER.
CARNE GUISADA.
THE MEAT JUST FALLS APART
IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE SAUCE
IS REALLY, REALLY YUMMY.
TO ME, IT TASTES LIKE POT ROAST
WITH CHILI PEPPERS.
MEXICAN POT ROAST.
IT REMINDS ME OF THE WAY
MY MOM USED TO MAKE IT.
'CAUSE IT'S THE WAY BOB'S MOM
USED TO MAKE IT.
ONE LENGUA,
ONE GROUND BEEF.
AND ONCE THEY STARTED
COOKING HER WAY,
THERE WAS NO GOING BACK.
CHICHARRON PLATES.
THEIR EMPANADAS
ARE VERY GOOD.
A DOZEN TAMALES
FOR YOU, SIR.
THE TAMALES ARE EXCELLENT.
THEY'RE HOMEMADE, AS WELL.
HOW MANY TAMALES DO YOU
GO THROUGH IN A DAY?
40, 50 DOZEN.
OH, BOY.
HOW DO WE GET STARTED?
PORK...
PORK BUTT--
IT'S ACTUALLY SHOULDER MEAT,
VERSUS THE HIND QUARTER
MEAT.
SALT,
PEELED GARLIC WHOLE.
COVER IT WITH WATER.
OKAY, SO WE LET IT SIMMER
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT TWO, THREE HOURS.
TILL THAT PORK
JUST FALLS APART?
JUST BREAKS APART, YES.
ONCE IT'S DONE, I PUT IT
IN THE MIXER AND SHRED IT.
GOT IT.
SO WE GOT OUR PORK
ALL MIXED UP.
NOW WE JUST
ADD THE LARD.
GET THAT NICE AND HOT.
PURéED GARLIC,
CUMIN AND PEPPER.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
TO BIND 'EM, YEAH.
SO IT PURéES UP EASY,
AND IT MIXES INTO THIS EVENLY?
YES.
AND NOW I ADD
THE PURéED GUAJILLO PEPPERS,
COOKED PORK.
SO WE'LL LET THIS GO FOR,
WHAT, ANOTHER 20 MINUTES...
15, 20 MINUTES.
AND THEN LET IT COOL, AND THEN
THIS IS GONNA BE THE MIXTURE
THAT'S GONNA GO
INTO OUR TAMALES?
YES.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE PREPARED MASA
FOR THE TAMALE.
PREPARED MASA.
SO ALL THIS IS
IS THE CORN AND WATER?
AND THEN YOU ADD...
A LITTLE MELTED MANTECA.
MELTED MANTECA, YES.
IT'S BASICALLY
CLEAN PORK FAT.
CHILI POWDER--
THIS IS FOR COLOR ONLY,
NOT FOR TASTE OR ANYTHING--
AND SALT, WATER.
OKAY. CRANK IT,
AND MIX IT.
AS SOON AS ALL THE INGREDIENTS
ARE INCORPORATED,
IT'S READY TO GO.
SCOOP SOME ON THE TABLE.
AND WE HAVE SOME CORN HUSKS
THAT HAVE BEEN SOAKED IN WATER.
PUT A DOLLOP ON THERE.
YOU SPREAD IT
RIGHT TO THE EDGE.
YEP.
FILL IT WITH THE PORK
THAT WE PREPARED.
BOY, YOU PUT A NICE AMOUNT
OF FILLING IN THAT.
FOLD IT OVER THE BACK,
AND THERE YOU GO.
AND THIS IS GONNA
GO IN THE STEAMER.
YES.
NOW HOW LONG
WILL IT STEAM?
AN HOUR.
(whistles) SO THAT'S
RIDICULOUSLY HOT.
OH, YEAH.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
THAT PORK--NICE, MOIST,
RIGHT AMOUNT OF SEASONING.
I LIKE THE MEAT RATIO.
VERY SELDOM
DO YOU EVER SEE A TAMALE
WITH THAT LITTLE MASA
AND THAT MUCH MEAT.
MMM. GREAT JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
TAMALES
ARE JUST SO PERFECT.
TAMALES.
RIGHT THICKNESS,
THE MEAT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
THEY MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
OF COURSE,
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING WOULD MELT
IN A SOUTH TEXAS SUMMER.
HOT OUTSIDE.
THIS IS NOTHING.
IT GETS WORSE THAN THIS?
YES, SIR.
GOOD THING BOB'S STILL
CRANKING OUT THE SNOBALLS...
YAY, SNOBALLS.
ON HIS ORIGINAL
SNOBALL MACHINE...
I'VE NEVER
SEEN THIS BEFORE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
AT BOB'S TACO STATION
IN ROSENBERG, TEXAS...
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
BOB ALANIS...
MA'AM, I CAN HELP YOU HERE.
AND HIS NEPHEW PACO...
TWO CARNE GUISADA.
HAVE BEEN SERVING UP THEIR
FAMILY'S MEXICAN FAVORITES...
A DOZEN TAMALES.
FOR ALMOST 20 YEARS.
THE BEST TAMALES.
THEY'RE SO GOOD.
BUT WHAT STARTED IT ALL WAS
SOMETHING CALLED A SNOBALL...
YAY, SNOBALLS.
AND IT BEGAN
WITH A BLOCK OF ICE.
IT'S THE PERFECT THING
TO GET--
A CUP OF ICE
WITH SOME FLAVOR ON IT.
CHERRY, COTTON CANDY,
DREAMSICLE, MARGARITA,
ICE CREAM,
LEMON-LIME, LECHE?
LECHE--IT'S LIKE
A MILK FLAVOR.
WHY IS IT CALLED A SNOBALL?
BECAUSE THE ICE IS SO SOFT,
IT'S LIKE SNOW.
THE GURGLING MONSTROSITY
WE SEE BEHIND US--
'CAUSE I DON'T GET TO SAY
"GURGLING MONSTROSITY" ENOUGH--
THIS IS OUR ICEMAKER.
WE FILL THESE STEEL CANISTERS
ABOUT 2 GALLONS OF WATER.
WHAT'S THIS SOLUTION
INSIDE OF HERE?
THIS IS WATER
MIXED WITH GLYCOL,
WHICH IS AN ACCELERATION PROCESS
TO FREEZE THE ICE.
THE GLYCOL CAN GET SUPER, SUPER
COLD, BUT IT WON'T FREEZE.
RIGHT.
IF THAT WAS JUST WATER,
WHEN THIS WATER FROZE,
THAT WATER WOULD FREEZE.
RIGHT.
OKAY, SO YOU TAKE THIS...
BRING IT OVER HERE.
RUN SOME HOT WATER ON 'EM.
AND THIS IS JUST GONNA
POP OUT THE ICE.
GET THE BAG READY.
ICE, ICE, BABY.
OH, I DIDN'T SAY THAT.
YOU READY?
PUT THE BAG RIGHT HERE.
CATCH IT...
WHOA, YEAH.
I'M READY.
BRING IT. YOU GOT IT?
THERE YOU GO.
JEEZ. I'VE BIRTHED A WALRUS
EASIER THAN THAT.
LET'S GO MAKE
SOME SNOBALLS.
OKAY.
OUR ICE BLOCK IN HERE.
RATCHET THIS.
SECURE THE ICE BLOCK
SO IT WON'T RATTLE AS MUCH.
WE PUSH THE ICE
THROUGH THE BLADES.
SO IT SHAVES THE ICE
THAT THIN,
IT'S LIKE SNOW.
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S CRAZY.
IT ACTUALLY FEELS LIKE SNOW.
ALL THESE FLAVORS. OKAY.
I THINK I'M GONNA GO...
DREAMSICLE IS GOOD.
OKAY, DREAMSICLE.
ALL RIGHT.
SO I JUST POUR IT
RIGHT ON THE TOP?
POUR SOME IN THE CENTER.
DROWN IT.
OKAY.
THEN THROW
SOME CREAM IN HERE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME,
"A," WE'VE HAD A SNOBALL
ON TRIPLE "D,"
AND "B," THE FIRST TIME
IN MY ENTIRE LIFE
I'VE EVER PUT MILK IN ONE.
DUDE, THIS IS NUTS.
THAT TASTES JUST LIKE
A 50-50 BAR.
THIS IS NOTHING
LIKE A SNOW CONE.
NO.
THE FLAVORS
REALLY COME OUT AT YOU.
THAT'S WHY
IT'S A SNOBALL.
YOU WANT TO TRY THIS?
THIS IS KILLER.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
I LIKE IT
'CAUSE IT'S SWEET.
LOTS OF SYRUP,
A LOT OF SYRUP.
HOW IS IT?
GOOD.
(mumbling)
GOOD. THIS IS GOOD.
MMM.
IT'S REALLY SOFT.
IT'S NOT ALL FROZEN.
YOU JUST HAPPENED TO OPEN UP
A LITTLE SNOBALL STATION,
AND THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
YOU GOT THIS SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
AFTER THEY CONVERTED TO TACOS,
I JUST KEPT COMING AROUND.
I LOVE TO COME HERE
EVERY DAY.
(woman) CHICKEN TACO SALAD.
IT'S JUST AWESOME.
WE HAVE TO HAVE IT.
NEXT TIME I COME TO HOUSTON
IN THE WINTER,
PLEASE, LOAD ME UP ABOUT SIX
DOZEN OF THOSE FLOUR TORTILLAS
IN THAT '67, ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
YOU GUYS ARE GREAT.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
PACO, GREAT JOB.
SO WAS THAT A KILLER ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
DON'T WORRY, WE GOT PLENTY MORE
JOINTS ALL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO THERE'S VEGAN...
THERE'S VEE-GAN,
THERE'S VAY-GAN,
AND THERE'S VENTRILOQUISM.
(laughing)
YOU'RE DOING
A GREAT SHOW HERE.