HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE YOU MAKING?
A HARVARD DOUBLE BURGER.
BURGERS,
STEAKS AND CHOPS.
MMM, MMM!
IN CAMBRIDGE, MASSACHUSETTS...
THIS IS
THE PLACE TO GO.
A BURGER LEGEND
DOIN' 'EM EVERY WHICH WAY...
(woman) THE KEVIN GARNETT.
FOR ALMOST 50 YEARS.
HARVARD DOUBLE.
MMM, HOW'D I DO?
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
IT'S A REALLY FUN PLACE.
THANK YOU.
THE DIVE BAR...
THIS IS PERFECT.
DOIN' A TOP CHOP.
PORKCHOPS
ARE TO DIE FOR.
AND MADE-TO-ORDER
MAC & CHEESE.
MMM. CREAMY DREAMY.
YOU COULD SELL THIS.
I ALREADY DO.
AND OUTSIDE HOUSTON...
EVERYTHING'S
EXCELLENT HERE.
THE MEAT MARKET
TURNED STEAK HOUSE...
ORDER'S UP.
WHERE THEY'RE HAND-CUTTIN'
1,500 STEAKS A WEEK...
14-OUNCE T-BONE, MEDIUM.
AND THE HOMEMADE SAUSAGE
IS SMOKIN' OUT BACK.
LOOK AT THE JUICE
COMIN' OUT OF THAT.
PEOPLE DIP IT AND EAT IT,
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
MMM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, AS A CHEF, I'M ALWAYS
INTERESTED IN THE RECIPE.
WHAT'S THE RECIPE FOR
A GREAT TRIPLE "D" LOCATION?
IT'S GOTTA HAVE HISTORY,
IT'S GOTTA HAVE STORY,
IT'S GOTTA HAVE CHARACTER,
IT'S GOTTA HAVE LOCATION,
AND IT'S GOTTA HAVE
GREAT FOOD.
SO HERE WE ARE--
CAMBRIDGE, MASS.,
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM HARVARD UNIVERSITY,
TO CHECK OUT THE RECIPE
FOR SUCCESS AT THIS JOINT,
MR. BARTLEY'S BURGER COTTAGE.
(man) MEDIUM-RARE TO GO,
COMING UP.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST BURGERS
I'VE EVER HAD ANYWHERE.
HERE'S THE HARVARD DOUBLE.
IT'S LIKE
A HARVARD CLUBHOUSE
WITH A BUNCH OF YOUR FRIENDS
AND, YOU KNOW, GREAT BURGERS.
PICK 'EM UP!
I LIKE BEING ACROSS FROM
HARVARD YARD COOKING MY BURGERS.
IN THE SHOP BILLY BARTLEY'S DAD
OPENED THE YEAR BILLY WAS BORN.
SIX BURGERS, GOIN' ON.
BILLY PICKED UP
THE SPATULA WHEN HE WAS 13.
PROVOLONE SUPREME,
MEDIUM-RARE.
DUDE, A LOT OF TIME
BACK HERE, HUH?
ABSOLUTELY. 37 YEARS.
THIS IS WHAT I WANT TO DO.
I MEAN, I-I WANT TO COOK.
MEDIUM-WELL,
COMIN' AT YA.
WHAT MAKES
A BURGER HERE SO GOOD?
WE'RE STARTIN' WITH THE BEST,
100% CHUCK.
SIRLOIN'S TOO LEAN.
CHUCK HAS THE TASTE.
LET'S WORK WITH
THIS 85-15 AND GET GOIN'.
STEP BACK.
OKAY, SO WE
LOAD UP THE HOPPER.
WE'RE NOT SEASONIN' THIS,
NO FILLER.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
THERE WE GO--
MONEY!
THAT'S A GOOD--
SO YOU JUST TAKE IT
AND IT GOES RIGHT INTO A BOWL?
AND ALL DAY LONG
IT GOES LIKE THIS.
SHE GETS A WORKOUT.
SHE? SHE HAS A NAME.
THE S.S. BURGER MACHINE.
THE S.S. BURGER--
SO WE'RE GONNA--
WE JUST KEEP
KNOCKING 'EM OUT LIKE THIS,
THEN WE GO
TO THE FLATTOP.
ABSOLUTELY.
LET'S GO COOK ONE.
ON IT GOES,
RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
THAT'S IT, AND WE'RE
JUST GONNA WEIGHT IT.
WE WANT TO SEAR IT QUICKLY.
THAT'S THE WHOLE POINT.
AND YOU THINK
THIS IS HELPING IT.
YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME
I'M GONNA BE ABLE
TO TELL. OKAY.
SEVEN MINUTES,
THREE AND A HALF EACH SIDE.
YEAH.
LOOK AT THE CRUST
ON THAT.
NO SALT, NO PEPPER,
NO NOTHING WHILE IT'S COOKING.
A LITTLE BIT
OF KOSHER SALT.
ROCK AND ROLL, WHICH
ONE ARE WE GONNA HAVE?
A HARVARD DOUBLE BURGER.
HARVARD DOUBLE.
TWO BIG PATTIES,
ONIONS, MUSHROOM
AND A LOAD OF BARBECUE SAUCE.
(Boston accent) HARVARD.
(normal voice)
I'M NOT SAYING IT RIGHT?
(normal voice) NO.
WHAT ARE YOU,
A YALE GUY?
MAKE THE BURGER.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
A LITTLE BIT OF BACON ON HERE.
BARBECUE SAUCE.
JUST A LITTLE.
MORE BURGER.
MORE BACON.
DO YOU CHARGE TUITION
TO EAT THIS THING?
GRILLED ONIONS,
GRILLED PEPPERS.
YOU'RE SERIOUSLY GONNA
STACK ALL THAT ON THERE?
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
THERE'S NO WAY.
BUT YOU'RE
A PROFESSIONAL.
I THINK YOU CAN DO IT.
I'LL MAKE A BET WITH YOU.
IF YOU CAN EAT IT
IN ONE BITE, IT'S YOURS.
IF YOU CAN'T,
THE CAMARO'S MINE.
HOW'D I DO?
RIGHT HERE, JUST--
IS THERE SOME RIGHT THERE?
IS THERE A LOT?
DO YOU HAVE
A SMALL CARPET SHAMPOOER?
DOES THIS MEAN
I DON'T GET THE CAMARO?
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE BURGER'S REALLY JUICY.
AND THE HARVARD DOUBLE'S
A CLASSIC--
BEEN ON THE BOARD
SINCE THE JOINT OPENED...
THERE IT IS,
VEGGIE BRADY SWEET.
BUT BILLY'S ALWAYS
LOOKING TO ADD TO THE MENU.
EVERY BURGER
HAS ITS OWN CHARACTER,
AND I THINK THAT'S PART
OF THE FUN OF COMING HERE.
YOU GOT
YOUR POLITICIANS...
JOHN KERRY BURGER
WITH AMERICAN CHEESE.
AND YOU GOT YOUR JOCKS...
THE KEVIN GARNETT
WITH SWEET POTATO FRIES.
IT'S GOT JACK CHEESE,
CHILI AND SOUR CREAM.
OR MAYBE YOU'RE
A NEW ENGLAND PATRIOT'S FAN.
BRADY, MEDIUM-RARE
WITH FRIES.
GREAT, THANK YOU.
THE BRADY BURGER
WITH THE GUACAMOLE.
EXCELLENT.
SUPER JUICY,
BUT THE KEY IS THIS CRUST
FROM IT COOKING
ON THE FLATTOP.
THEY HAVE
THE BEST BURGERS ANYWAY.
AND WORD DOES GET AROUND.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
HOUSTON, TEXAS.
HOUSTON, TEXAS!
FROM MIAMI.
WE KNOW OUR MEAT IN CHICAGO,
AND THIS IS GOOD BEEF.
IT'S THE FIRST TIME
I HAD THE ONION RINGS.
WE DON'T
HAVE THAT IN DENMARK.
YOU'VE GOTTA FEEL SORRY
FOR THAT DUDE.
THEY'RE REALLY GOOD. YOU CAN
TASTE THE FRESHNESS OF 'EM.
WE'RE DOING ONION RINGS--
A LARGE SPANISH ONION...
OKAY, NICE BIG,
FRESH, CLEAN...
YEAH.
THIN-SLICED
SO THEY'LL COOK.
THEY'RE GOING
RIGHT IN TO THE EVAP.
EVAP, AS IN
EVAPORATED MILK?
EVAPORATED MILK.
EVAP.
JUST GET 'EM WET.
THE QUICKER YOU DO THIS, THE
BETTER THIS RING IS GONNA BE.
OKAY.
RING IT OUT, USING
THE WHOLE CORN FLOUR.
THIS IS JUST REGULAR
OLD CORN FLOUR.
NOTHING, NO SEASONING,
NOTHING.
SHAKE OFF THE EXCESS.
ALL RIGHT.
LIGHT SHAKE.
THAT'S IT?
DOWN IT GOES.
SO WHEN THEY COME OUT, DO YOU
SALT THEM, OR DO THEY SALT THEM?
NO, CUSTOMERS SALT.
EVERYBODY SAYS, OH, YOU NEED TO
SALT IT RIGHT AS IT COMES OUT
OF THE FRYER--
THE WAY WE MOVE,
YOU'RE SALTIN' IT RIGHT WHEN IT
COMES OUT OF THE FRYER.
I LIKE THAT ONE.
ABSOLUTELY.
OKAY, ARE THEY DONE?
THEY ARE DONE.
OKAY.
THOSE MIGHT BE HOT.
H-H-H-HAA. THAT'S
A GOOD ONION RING.
THAT'S THE BEST
ONION RING I EVER HAD.
IT'S EXACTLY THE RIGHT CUT--
NICE AND THIN AND CRISPY.
YOU GOT IT
EXACTLY THE RIGHT WAY.
SO HERE'S MY METHOD--NICE COOL
KETCHUP RIGHT HERE.
AND THEN, MMM.
THIS RIGHT HERE, THAT'S
ORCHESTRATION RIGHT THERE.
GREAT ONION RING.
I APPRECIATE IT.
GREAT ONION RING. MY SON HUNTER
WOULD DIG THESE.
COME ON,
YOU WANT TO TRY ONE?
THAT'S THE AUTHORITY
ON ONION RINGS OVER THERE.
OH, YEAH
NO PLACE HAS ONION RINGS
AS GOOD AS THAT.
GOOD ONION RING?
MM-HMM.
SEE? YOU GOT THE HUNTER
SEAL OF APPROVAL RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ROCK ON.
IT'S PERFECT.
VERY CRISPY.
I DON'T USUALLY LIKE ONION
RINGS, SO I'M A BIG FAN.
YOU GOTTA KNOW PEOPLE
COME FOR THE ONION RINGS.
500 POUNDS A WEEK,
AND THE HAND-CUT
SWEET POTATO FRIES.
BIG AND PLUMP,
DELICIOUS.
EVEN HOMEMADE SLAW
AND RUSSIAN DRESSING.
PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC
ON THE DANCE FLOOR.
OF CAMBRIDGE.
SOME NICE COLESLAW.
SO THIN-SLICED CABBAGE.
AND YOU GUYS MAKE THE SLAW,
DRESSING AND EVERYTHING?
OH, YEAH. SUGAR, A LITTLE
SEASON SALT, CELERY SEED,
A LITTLE CIDER VINEGAR, A LITTLE
OIL, A LITTLE RED CABBAGE...
STRAIGHT-UP SLAW.
A LITTLE CARROTS,
KOSHER SALT, WHITE PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER, MAYONNAISE,
AND THEN RUSSIAN DRESSING.
THIS IS MY
MOTHER'S RECIPE.
SO THIS IS
A PICKLE RELISH...
CHOPPED SPANISH ONION.
AND KETCHUP
AND MAYONNAISE.
WE HAVE A COUPLE
SECRET INGREDIENTS--
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
SEASONED SALT,
WHITE PEPPER, BLACK PEPPER,
MAPLE SYRUP.
IN THE RUSSIAN DRESSING?
IT IS, YEAH;
THAT'S HOW SHE GOES.
SIMPLE.
MMM, NOW THAT'S
WHAT I NEEDED RIGHT THERE.
SOME TANG,
MONSTER FLAVOR PROFILE.
YOU TASTE THE MEAT, THE SLAW.
DRESSING'S GOT A LITTLE POP,
A LITTLE SWEETNESS
COMES IN BEHIND THAT.
YOU GOT YOURSELF
A GREAT RECIPE.
YOU BRING ALL
THE PIECES TOGETHER,
AND THAT'S WHY
YOU GET DYNAMITE BURGER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT REALLY IS.
EXCELLENT.
(Billy)
ON THE DECK, MICHELLE.
I WAS TOLD THAT THIS IS
THE BEST BURGER IN TOWN.
A SUPREME WITH
BLUE CHEESE AND SWEET.
IT'S A GREAT BURGER.
(Billy) HERE SHE IS!
HANDS DOWN, IT ALL
STARTS WITH QUALITY,
AND YOU'RE
LEADING THAT WAY.
THIS IS
THE PLACE TO GO.
MMM. VERY GOOD.
YOU'RE THE MAN.
GREAT JOB, BILLY.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, GUYS.
WHAT A GUY.
UP NEXT...
THE FOOD'S AMAZING HERE.
WE'RE HEADING WEST
TO SAN FRANCISCO...
WE GOT A PULLED PORK
AND A CHOP, TABLE THREE.
TO A HOLE IN THE WALL...
(whistles)
IT'S 5-STAR DIVE BAR.
THAT'S A HOLE IN ONE.
5-STAR DIVE BAR.
I'M HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO
ON CLEMENT STREET.
NOW RIGHT OVER THERE
IS THE GOLF COURSE.
AND RIGHT HERE, WELL, THIS IS
THE TEE OFF BAR & GRILL.
IT'S YOUR BASIC
19th-HOLE BEER JOINT.
IT'S JUST
WHAT YOU WOULD EXPECT,
UNTIL YOU
OPEN UP THE MENU.
FIRING PORTERHOUSE.
IT'S NOT YOUR
AVERAGE PUB GRILL.
PORKCHOP
WITH APRICOT RELISH.
THIS IS PERFECT.
FOOD THAT YOU WOULD EXPECT
TO GET IN A 5-STAR RESTAURANT.
THAT'S WHAT'S SO COOL
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
IT'S 5-STAR DIVE BAR.
5-STAR DIVE BAR.
THANKS TO PAUL GROARKE...
TABLE TWO.
WHO BOUGHT THIS JOINT
WITH HIS WIFE CRYSTAL...
THANK YOU, BABE.
THREE AND A HALF
YEARS AGO.
SHE WAS WORKING
IN A BAR,
I WAS WORKING AT A RESTAURANT,
AND WE DECIDED TO GO FOR IT.
TABLE TWO'S OUT.
I DIDN'T WANT TO WASTE MY
EXPERIENCE IN FINE DINING.
SO HE BROUGHT IT HERE.
WE GOT A PULLED PORK SANDWICH,
PORTERHOUSE
AND A GRILLED ARTICHOKE.
I TRY TO MAKE EVERYTHING AS
CLOSE TO SCRATCH AS POSSIBLE.
PICK UP!
LIKE THIS HEAVY HITTER...
THE PORKCHOPS
ARE TO DIE FOR.
DOUBLE-CUT
WITH APRICOT RELISH.
JUST WHAT I EXPECTED WHEN I SAW
THE TEE OFF BAR & GRILL.
YEAH.
OHH, I BET YOU THEY HAVE A GREAT
DOUBLE-CUT PORKCHOP IN THERE.
SO WE GOT
THE FULL LOIN HERE.
BASICALLY, I JUST
GO DOWN THE BONE.
YOU ACTUALLY TAKE THE TIME
TO BUTCHER DOWN.
YOU GOTTA GET DIRTY.
YOU GOTTA GET YOUR HANDS WET.
I DIG IT, BROTHER.
YOU HAVE ME AT HELLO.
WANT TO GET
A NICE FAT CHOP.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT MONSTER.
A DOUBLE-CUT CHOP BONE
IS IN THE CENTER.
YOU BASICALLY GOT TWO CHOPS,
BUT WITH ONE BONE.
PRETTY MUCH.
WE'RE GONNA BRINE THESE?
YEAH, EQUAL PARTS
SALT, SUGAR,
DISSOLVE IT IN HOT WATER,
AND JUST ADD PICKLING SPICE.
YOU GOTTA LET IT
COOL DOWN A LITTLE BEFORE
YOU PUT THE PORK IN IT.
WHEN IT GETS TO ROOM
TEMPERATURE, THEN WE'LL PUT IT
ON THE PORKCHOP.
POUR IT IN THERE, STICK IT
IN THE FRIDGE AND LET IT SIT.
NOW HOW LONG WILL YOU
LET THIS GO FOR?
I USUALLY
SOAK IT OVERNIGHT.
WE'LL MAKE THE APRICOT RELISH
WHILE THAT'S BRINING.
YEAH.
DIG IT. I LIKE YOUR
MIXING BOWL SETUP HERE.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT ALL
INTO THIS?
PRETTY MUCH.
OKAY, WE GOT SOME ONION,
UH, GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
A LITTLE
RED BELL PEPPERS.
I'LL JUST KEEP DOING
THE CLEANUP HERE.
THANK YOU.
TOMATOES. I LIKE
THE APRICOT IDEA.
THANK YOU.
I'M A GOOD SOUS-CHEF.
I DUMP IN
SOME RED WINE VINEGAR.
A LITTLE SALT.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
JUST LET THAT REST
FOR A WHILE.
THE LONGER IT GOES,
THE MORE IT MACERATES.
THE BETTER IT GETS.
SO BRINE CHOP,
ACHIOTE PASTE...
SPRINKLE IT IN THERE.
A LITTLE OIL.
YEP.
THAT GOOD?
A LITTLE MORE.
THERE YOU GO.
JUST THROW
THAT CHOP RIGHT IN.
I LET THE CHOP
DO THE WORK.
IT BECOMES YOUR
MORTAR, PESTLE RIGHT THERE.
EXACTLY.
BRINING IT WASN'T ENOUGH.
IT'S LIKE A BARBECUE AT THE U.N.
EXACTLY.
LOOK AT THAT. THERE'S GONNA BE
SOME DYNAMITE COLOR ON THERE.
OH, YEAH. I GIVE IT
THE CRISSCROSS ON BOTH SIDES.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU ROLL.
SEVEN, TEN MINUTES.
OHH!
I SERVE IT WITH
DEEP-FRIED SWEET CORN.
NO! THAT'S A NEW ONE.
HOW LONG'S THAT GONNA PARTY?
WE'RE AT THREE MINUTES.
THIS IS ODD.
ODD?
YEAH, VERY STRANGE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THAT BEFORE.
TO BURN SOME
OF THE EXCESS OIL
OFF IT, I THROW IT
ON THE GRILL RIGHT BEFORE.
A LITTLE CHAR ON IT.
THEN IT GOES WITH
GARLIC MASHED POTATOES,
GRILLED ASPARAGUS,
GRILLED APRICOTS
TO ACCOMPANY
THE APRICOT RELISH.
OKAY, SO THEY'RE BLANCHED OFF.
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE? I LIKE IT.
PUT A LITTLE SALT ON THERE,
A LITTLE CRACKED PEPPER.
WE'RE READY TO THROW
THE GARLIC MASHED POTATOES DOWN
AND PLATE IT UP.
NICE.
SMALL PORTIONS HERE
AT TEE OFF.
ASPARAGUS, AND THEN THIS,
THE MOMENT OF TRUTH.
SO JUST WHEN I GOT DONE
SHOOTING 175
OVER ON THE 9-HOLE,
I DIDN'T EXPECT I'D FIND THIS.
LOOK AT THAT--NICE MEDIUM-RARE
ON THAT BAD BOY.
DUDE, THAT IS
SOME PRECIOUS PORK.
WOW, IT'S
COOKED PERFECTLY.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT SALSA
ON TOP OF THAT. MMM, MMM!
THAT ACHIOTE RUB
ON THE OUTSIDE
GIVES A LITTLE SPIKE
OF SOME PEPPER TO IT.
YEAH.
MMM! I GOTTA TRY
THIS FUNKY CORN.
MMM, I LIKE
THE TEXTURE.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE EVER HAD
FRIED CORN LIKE THIS,
BUT I LIKE IT.
MMM, ASPARAGUS
IS RIGHT ON POINT.
I'M TELLING YOU WHAT, MAN.
NICE GARLIC MASH.
THAT'S UP THERE WITH SOME
OF THE BEST CHOPS I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S TENDER, JUICY,
A SWEETNESS OF THE RELISH.
WE GOT A PULLED PORK
AND A CHOP, TABLE NUMBER THREE.
BUT PAUL'S GOT IT GOING ON,
I'LL TELL YA.
IT'S A REALLY FUN PLACE.
I GOTTA GET FOR THE KIDS.
PLAY SOME POOL,
SOME PING-PONG OUT BACK,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
AND THEN ONCE
YOU'VE HAD A FEW DRINKS
AND YOU'RE
READY FOR SOME FOOD...
THANK YOU.
THE FOOD'S AMAZING.
FROM PORTERHOUSE STEAKS...
OH, I LOVE
THE PORTERHOUSE.
TO PULLED PORK SANDWICHES.
WITH PAUL'S
OWN BARBECUE SAUCE.
WOW, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
MY FAVORITE IS
THE MACARONI AND CHEESE.
THE SIGNATURE DISH HERE...
MMM.
MADE WITH PANCETTA.
PANCETTA--ITALIAN BACON.
I LOVE PANCETTA SO MUCH,
MY MIDDLE NAME
SHOULD HAVE BEEN PANCETTA.
DON'T BE SHY WITH THAT.
AND I JUST KINDA
ROLL IT OUT.
WELL, MY MOUTH
IS ACTUALLY WATERING.
I'M GONNA SAUTé IT
IN A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
TO HELP IT DO IT'S THING.
OKAY, SO HOW LONG'S
THAT GONNA COOK DOWN?
UNTIL IT'S NICE AND CRISPY.
AND I ADD SOME HEAVY CREAM.
RIGHT INTO THE FAT.
HERE AT PAUL'S
DIET CENTER.
WE SERVE IT WITH A HEALTHY
STRAWBERRY SALAD, THOUGH.
YEAH, THAT'S KIND OF LIKE
ANCHORING THE QUEEN MARY
WITH A PAPER CLIP.
EXACTLY.
THIS IS JUST SHREDDED CHEDDAR
AND MONTEREY.
WOW, DUDE. DO YOU STIR THIS
OR ANYTHING?
YEAH.
AND THEN I ADD MORE CHEESE.
IT'S A 4-CHEESE BLEND.
ASIAGO, PARM--
ASIAGO, FONTINA,
PARMESAN AND PROVOLONE.
WE'RE HERE
INTO FONDUE HEAVEN.
AND NOW I ADD
THE ZITI NOODLES.
THERE'S NOT EVEN ENOUGH ROOM
TO PUT NOODLES.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME
TO DO WITH THIS? GO AHEAD.
OH.
THAT'S CRAZY.
OKAY, SO BEFORE
I THROW IT IN THE OVEN,
I SHAVE SOME FRESH ASIAGO--
THERE YOU GO--
AND SOME FRESH PARM.
'CAUSE THERE'S NOT ENOUGH
CHEESE IN THERE.
NO.
OHH, LOOK AT THAT.
WELL, I GOT IT DOWN
INTO A SMALLER CAST-IRON PAN.
ONE MORE LITTLE COAT--
ASIAGO AND PARMESAN.
OKAY, SO THEN IT GOES
NIGHT-NIGHT FOR WHAT?
ABOUT EIGHT
TO TEN MINUTES.
DUDE, YOU GOT ISSUES.
I KNOW.
IS SHE READY, CAPTAIN?
SHE'S READY.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS. MMM.
IT'S NOT OVER YET.
A LITTLE MORE...
MORE CHEESE.
AND JUST TOP IT OFF WITH SOME
CHIVES AND CRACKED PEPPER.
YOU SURE WE'RE DONE?
'CAUSE, I MEAN, WE GOT
THE REST OF THE DAY.
SUPER CREAMY DREAMY.
MMM.
THE BLEND OF CHEESES,
I REALLY DIG,
AND I'M A PANCETTA JUNKIE,
SO THAT PLAYS RIGHT INTO IT.
MMM. YOU COULD SELL THIS.
I ALREADY DO.
CREAMY, SILKY,
CHEESY GOODNESS.
JUST BURSTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE THIS
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
IT IS THE FUNKIEST,
BUT IT IS THE COOLEST.
'CAUSE I CAN EAT LIKE A GOD
AND DRINK LIKE A FISH...
CHEERS, KIDS.
ALL AT THE SAME TIME.
AWESOME.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
NICE TO MEET YOU, BROTHER.
I APPRECIATE IT.
YOU'RE GONNA SEE ME AND MY
BOYS--I LIVE IN SANTA ROSA.
RIGHT ON. COOL.
WE'RE NOT FAR AWAY. THIS
WILL NOT BE MY LAST VISIT.
RIGHT ON, MAN.
NEXT STOP...
(woman) TOM'S CHOICE.
WE'RE HEADING
SOUTH OF HOUSTON.
DOWN-HOME,
FAMILY-STYLE RESTAURANT.
FOR HAND-CUT STEAKS...
LOOK AT THAT.
AND HOUSE-SMOKED SAUSAGE.
MY MOUTH'S RUNNING.
IT'S GREAT ROLLIN'
THE '67 AROUND HERE.
I'M SOUTH OF HOUSTON,
ALMOST BY GALVESTON,
IN A LITTLE TOWN
CALLED KEMAH.
NOW THERE'S A LOT
GOING ON IN THIS AREA.
THERE'S THIS THING--
WHAT'S THIS PLACE CALLED?
OH, YEAH, SOMETHING LIKE
THE JOHNSON SPACE CENTER?
YOU KNOW, MISSION CONTROL?
HOW COOL IS THAT?
BUT THERE'S ALSO THIS GREAT
LITTLE EATERY HERE--
T-BONE TOM'S,
WHERE I HEAR THESE FOLKS HAVE
BEEN HAND-CUTTING THEIR STEAKS
FOR OVER 35 YEARS.
(woman) 14-OUNCE T-BONE,
MEDIUM.
THE FOOD'S EXCELLENT.
BACON-WRAPPED FILLET--
REALLY GOOD.
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
REAL DOWN-HOME,
FAMILY-STYLE RESTAURANT.
THE WAY IT'S BEEN
SINCE '73...
ORDER'S UP.
WHEN GENERAL MANAGER
ANNA KENNEDY
FIRST CAME TO WORK HERE.
TOM'S CHOICE.
IT WAS A MEAT MARKET.
WE ALWAYS SOLD BARBECUE.
IN 1983,
WE BECAME A RESTAURANT.
YOU CUT ALL THE STEAKS, ALL
THE BUTCHERING GOES ON HERE.
JUST LIKE ALWAYS.
AIN'T BROKE,
DON'T FIX IT.
HAMBURGERS OKAY?
SO WHEN BARRY TERRELL
BOUGHT THE JOINT
MORE THAN TEN YEARS AGO, HE
DIDN'T MESS WITH THE OLD MENU.
HE JUST ADDED TO IT,
LIKE THIS TOP-SELLER.
THAT'S A RIB EYE.
AFTER WE MARINATE IT,
WE CALL IT THE TOM'S CHOICE.
TENDER, JUICY,
VERY GOOD.
OKAY.
THAT'S A KNIFE.
YES, IT IS.
YOU GONNA CUT THESE UP--
WHAT SIZE STEAK?
12-OUNCE.
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKING MEAT,
NICE AND UNIFORM,
THEN THAT GOES
IN THE MARINADE.
THAT'S CORRECT.
WHAT ARE WE PUTTING IN IT?
THAT LOOKS LIKE OIL.
CANOLA CORN OIL BLEND,
SOY SAUCE.
THIS IS
THE WORCESTERSHIRE.
I'M SORRY?
WER-CHESTER-SHIRE SAUCE.
(speaks nonsense)
I CAN'T GET IT RIGHT EITHER.
PINEAPPLE JUICE.
YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A TERIYAKI TYPE THING.
SO YOU GOT YOUR SOY IN THERE FOR
YOUR LITTLE BIT OF YOUR SUGAR.
MM-HMM.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
AND WE PUT BLACK PEPPER.
AND MUSTARD.
DRY MUSTARD, CORRECT.
OKAY.
WE GET THAT
ALL MIXED UP.
GET ALL OF OUR STEAKS,
PUT THEM IN THE MARINADE.
WE REFRIGERATE THEM
FOR ONE DAY.
IN THIS.
WE SELL 'EM
THE NEXT DAY.
THE DAY BEFORE
THE NEXT DAY
IS THE DAY THAT
WE'RE GONNA SELL 'EM.
Y-YEAH,
WE MARINATE 'EM--
IN THE DAY.
OKAY, THESE
ARE READY TO GO?
THEY'VE BEEN
MARINATING THEIR DAY?
YES.
HOT CHARBROILER,
AND ON WE GO.
COOK US ONE UP.
NOW HOW DO YOU
LIKE YOUR STEAK?
I LIKE IT MEDIUM-RARE.
THAT'S ABOUT WHERE
I'LL TAKE MINE.
ALL RIGHT, WILL DO.
OKAY. OHH,
THERE YOU GO. AHH.
MMM, THAT'S A GREAT STEAK.
THAT REALLY IS.
MMM, THAT'S A NICE QUICK,
SIMPLE, EASY MARINADE.
YOU CAN'T IDENTIFY JUST
ONE OF THE FLAVORS.
WOW, THAT'S
A NICE PIECE OF MEAT.
TASTE THE MARINADE.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
I CAN GET IT LIKE I WANT IT.
HAMBURGER STEAK.
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN
A PLACE LIKE THIS BEFORE.
EVERYTHING'S EXCELLENT HERE,
MADE ALWAYS THE SAME WAY.
FROM
THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK...
EATING IT FOR 20 YEARS.
TO THE CHOPPED BEEF...
VERY GOOD.
TO THIS LOCAL FAVORITE.
SMOKED SAUSAGE.
(Anna) WE STUFF IT, AND THEN WE
SMOKE IT ON OUR PIT IN THE BACK.
ALL HERE.
(man) CAN'T BEAT IT.
THIS SAUSAGE
IS JUST PERFECT.
WHAT KIND OF SAUSAGE
ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
A POLISH SAUSAGE.
IT'S 50% BEEF,
50% PORK.
REALLY GOOD FAT,
GOOD WHITE FAT LIKE THAT
IS WHAT YOU WANT.
ONCE I GET IT UP THERE,
I'M GONNA MIX IT UP.
YOU'RE GONNA
PUT THAT IN THERE?
UH, NO.
WELL, WHO'S PUTTING THAT--
OH, AM I PUTTING THAT IN THERE?
YEAH, YOU'RE PUTTING
THAT IN THERE.
BUT I DON'T WANT TO MESS UP
MY BOBBY HAWAIIAN T-SHIRT.
WOULD YOU
LIKE AN APRON?
NOT SO MUCH.
OKAY. WE'RE GONNA
GRIND THE MEAT.
OOH!
OKAY, YOU READY?
FIRE AWAY.
OH, GOOD.
I THINK IT'S THE SNAP
AND THE CRACKLE
THAT JUST
GETS IT FOR ME.
SO NOW--
I'M GONNA PUT THAT
BACK UP THERE AGAIN.
YES, YOU ARE. UH-HUH.
ALL RIGHT,
FIRE IT UP.
OKAY.
OH, NOW IT'S JUST
REALLY CRANKING OUT.
YEAH.
MAKES A DIFFERENT SOUND.
IT'S NOT QUITE
AS POPPY AND SMACK-Y.
NO. RIGHT.
IT'S BREAKING UP, BUT IT'S
DEFINITELY SOME PORK SAUSAGE.
MM-HMM, MM-HMM.
OKAY. SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE SEASONING?
YES.
SEASON SALT.
WE BUY THIS FROM
A SPICE COMPANY IN THIS AREA.
THE PURPOSE OF THE WATER
IS TO HELP BLEND IT
THROUGH THE MEAT.
CURING SALT NEXT.
THIS IS THE MIX
OF NITRATE AND SALT.
MUSTARD SEED,
AND A LOT OF IT.
I'M GONNA
STIR IT ALL UP.
PUNCH BOWL AT THE MEAT BUFFET
PALACE IN FLAVOR TOWN.
YOU GOT THAT?
YOU WANT IT?
NO, JUST MAKING SURE
YOU GOT IT.
I GOT IT.
OKAY.
POUR ALL THIS
INTO OUR MEAT.
SO THEN WE'RE GONNA MIX
ALL THIS SAUSAGE.
YOU SAID
YOU'LL MIX THIS
FOR WHAT, TEN MINUTES, TILL
YOU MAKE SURE YOU REALLY GOT IT?
PROBABLY, YEAH.
AND NOW THAT
THE SEASONINGS MIXED IN,
WE GRIND IT ONE MORE TIME,
THEN WE START TO CASE IT.
THIS HOLDS
25 POUNDS OF MEAT.
OKAY.
READY?
CRANK IT. WHOA,
THAT JUST GETS GOING, HUH?
MM-HMM.
NATURAL CASINGS?
YES.
WE FUNNEL THIS OUT,
WE CUT 'EM INTO PIECES.
NOW HOW LONG
ARE THEY GONNA SMOKE?
AN HOUR AND A HALF.
OH, YEAH. OHH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
MY MOUTH'S STARTIN' TO--
YEAH, THIS IS GOOD.
HEAR THE LITTLE SNAP
OF THAT CASING?
AND LOOK AT THE JUICE
COMING OUT OF THAT?
MMM, THAT IS ABOUT...
AS TENDER A SAUSAGE I'VE
EVER TRIED. THAT'S GREAT.
AND THIS IS THE BARBECUE SAUCE
THAT YOU MAKE WITH IT?
YES, KETCHUP...
A LITTLE LIQUID SMOKE
WORCESTERSHIRE IN THERE?
A HINT OF RED PEPPER.
MMM, I LIKE
THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
YEAH.
YOU JUST SLICE IT UP LIKE THIS,
PEOPLE DIP IT AND EAT IT.
AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
MMM, GREAT SAUSAGE.
THANK YOU.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
THE BARBECUE SAUCE IS A REALLY
NICE COMPLEMENT TO IT.
MMM, OH, IT'S DELICIOUS.
HOT BEEF SANDWICH.
JUST SOME GOOD HOME COOKING--
BURGERS, ARMADILLO EGGS.
YEP, ARMADILLO EGGS.
THEY'RE AWESOME, MAN.
WHEN WE GET BACK, I'LL PICK UP
ONE OF THESE HOT MOLTEN NUGGETS.
LOOK AT THAT.
(Anna) TOM'S CHOICE,
MEDIUM-RARE.
AT T-BONE TOM'S
IN KEMAH, TEXAS...
HOW Y'ALL DOING
OVER HERE?
OWNER BARRY TERRELL'S
MOVING MORE THAN 3,000 POUNDS
OF BEEF EVERY WEEK.
STEAK SANDWICH.
THANK YOU. IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
I CAN GET IT LIKE I WANT IT.
THEY'RE EVEN
PACKING IT IN PEPPERS.
MMM.
I'M HAVING
THE ARMADILLO EGGS.
LIKE, CAN YOU FIND THESE
ANYWHERE ELSE?
I HAVEN'T SEEN 'EM
ANYWHERE ELSE.
I HAVEN'T SEEN 'EM.
A DEEP-FRIED JALAPEÑO STUFFED
WITH THE PRIDE OF TEXAS--
SMOKED BRISKET.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE THE DRY RUB
FOR THE BRISKET?
THAT'S RIGHT.
START WITH SALT.
IT'S A MESS OF SALT.
MM-HMM.
GRANULATED ONION.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
FINE-GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
PAPRIKA
AND RED PEPPER.
THIS CAME FROM TOM?
THIS IS ACTUALLY
T-BONE'S FATHER'S RECIPE.
SO YOU MIX THIS UP, AND THEN
WE'RE JUST GONNA RUB THIS.
RUB THAT SIDE.
FLIP THAT OVER.
AND THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
SO NOW HOW LONG'S IT GONNA
GO IN THE SMOKER FOR?
ABOUT 16 HOURS,
BETWEEN 165 AND 175.
LOWER AND SLOWER.
YEAH, IT'S
GONNA BE REAL TENDER.
WHOA! LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
LOOK AT HOW THE FAT ON TOP
OF THIS IS ALMOST INTO LIQUID.
'CAUSE ALL THAT FAT HAS BASTED
THAT MEAT WHILE IT COOKED.
OH, OH! YOU GONNA BREAK THIS
ALL THE WAY DOWN?
YEAH.
WELL, GIVE ME--JUST
GET INTO IT, DOCTOR, DOCTOR.
OKAY.
WHOA, OH.
LOOK AT THAT.
ISN'T THAT PRETTY?
LIKE A FINE WINE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT SMOKE RING
RIGHT THERE. MMM.
I PICK UP THE SMOKE FLAVOR,
BUT NOT OVERBEARING.
THE FAT IN THE MEAT,
THAT'S JUST GONNA MELT.
MMM. IT DOESN'T GET
ANY MORE TENDER THAN THAT.
NO.
BUT I DON'T WANT
TO FILL UP ON ALL THIS,
'CAUSE WE STILL GOTTA DEAL
WITH THOSE ARMADILLO EGGS.
THAT'S CORRECT.
WE CHOP IT UP
IN A BUFFALO CHOPPER.
LOAD IT UP WITH
HOMEMADE BARBECUE SAUCE,
THEN IT'S HEADED
FOR A JALAPEÑO.
SEEDED AND DEVEINED.
THESE ARE PICKLED.
YES, STUFF IT WITH
THE BRISKET AND...
BARBECUE SAUCE.
BRISKET MEETS BAKED POTATO--
TWICE COOKED.
PRETTY MUCH.
ROLL IT AROUND
IN THE FLOUR, BUTTERMILK,
TOSS THAT AROUND.
HOW MANY COME
WITH AN ORDER?
FOUR.
OF THAT SIZE?
YES.
OH! SO A DOUBLE DREDG-Y,
DIPPY, FLOURY...
CORRECT. CORRECT.
OKAY, AND THEN
INTO THE PANKO?
YES.
WOW, LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
WE'RE GONNA DROP THAT
IN THE FRYER, 350 DEGREES.
THAT'S CORRECT.
AND WHAT DO WE
SERVE THAT WITH?
RANCH DRESSING.
THEY'RE REALLY THIS SIZE?
YES, EVERYTHING'S BIG
IN TEXAS.
LOOK AT THAT.
FILLED WITH BARBECUE,
JALAPEÑOS.
MMM. OH, YEAH.
WOW. THE BARBECUE'S GREAT.
THE JALAPEÑO BEING A PICKLED
JALAPEÑO REALLY MAKES IT.
THAT'S AN ADDED LITTLE FLAVOR
THAT YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT.
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
I MEAN, KILLER, KILLER.
(woman) ARMADILLO EGGS.
THEY'RE AWESOME, MAN.
CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
THIS IS THE ONE PLACE
THAT WE'LL SAY,
T-BONE TOM'S,
EVERYBODY WILL COME.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
EVERYTHING'S GREAT
ABOUT IT.
IT'S REMARKABLE THAT
YOU KEPT IT THE WAY IT WAS.
SOMEONE CAME IN 30 YEARS AGO,
AND THEY COME IN NOW,
YOU WANT 'EM TO BE ABLE
TO HAVE THAT SAME EXPERIENCE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE HAD A BLAST HERE.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY OF MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
AND HOW ARE
THE GREEN BEANS HERE?
TASTE A LOT BETTER
THAN AT HOME.
SEE YOU LATER, BUDDY.
GOOD LUCK CLEA--
GOOD LUCK CLEANING YOUR ROOM
FOR THE NEXT FOUR YEARS.