HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
OH, THIS REALLY LOOKS GOOD. I
WISH WE COULD TRY SOME OF THIS.
TWISTS...
I LOVE THE GOAT CHEESE
GUACAMOLE.
AND TRADITIONS...
CHICKEN à LA KING.
STRAIGHT OUT OF 1950, 1960,
JUST RIGHT HERE.
IN CLEVELAND.
WE DO EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH
EVERY DAY.
THE MOD MEXICAN JOINT...
CREATIVITY
WITH TRADITION.
PUT THEIR TWIST...
BEFORE WE BRAISE IT WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE REST OF OUR COFFEE.
ON TAQUITOS.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
THAT IS RIGHTEOUS.
THANKS.
IN SANTA CRUZ, CALIFORNIA...
THEIR SEAFOOD'S
ALWAYS REALLY FRESH.
WHERE DOCKSIDE DINING...
A UNIQUE SETTING.
MEETS FRESH CALAMARI...
NICE AND CRISPY.
AND RAVIOLI
MADE FROM SCRATCH.
BUON APPETITO.
MMM. AWESOME.
AND IN CHAFFEE, NEW YORK...
SHEPHERDS PIE.
THE JOINT THAT'S BEEN
A TRADITION...
JUST LIKE IT WAS
IN THE OLD DAYS.
FOR MORE THAN 50 YEARS.
IT'S HOW YOUR GRANDMA
WOULD MAKE IT, YOU KNOW?
YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
AS I TRAVEL THE COUNTRY,
ONE OF THE FOODS
I LOVE TO CHECK OUT
IS MEXICAN FOOD.
I MEAN, SO MANY DIFFERENT
STYLES AND METHODS
AND INTERPRETATIONS--
YOU NAME IT.
ONE OF THE THINGS I'VE LEARNED
ON TRIPLE "D"
IS THERE IS GREAT
MEXICAN FOOD EVERYWHERE.
I'M IN CLEVELAND, OHIO, NOW
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT SAYS THEY'RE DOING
"MOD MEX."
OH, YEAH, THIS IS MOMOCHO.
TROUT PICKUP!
CREATIVITY
WITH THE TRADITION.
DUCK AND YAM ENCHILADAS.
I LOVE THE GOAT CHEESE
GUACAMOLE.
YOU DON'T GET THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
SALSA TRIO
PICKUP, PLEASE.
(woman)
NOTHING COMPARES TO THIS.
THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT ERIC HAS CREATED.
ONE TIME.
THAT'D BE CHEF AND OWNER
ERIC WILLIAMS...
ALCACHOFA--
PICK IT UP.
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT
ALMOST FOUR YEARS AGO
WITH A MISSION.
NOT ONLY PRODUCE
GOOD FOOD
BUT INTRODUCE NEW THINGS
TO CLEVELAND.
TWO TINGAS.
EVERYTHING'S BOLD,
LOTS OF FLAVORS...
(whistles)
THERE'S NO WALK-IN COOLERS.
THERE'S NO RE--
SERIOUSLY?
WE DO EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH EVERY DAY.
YEP, LIKE A DOZEN
DIFFERENT TAQUITOS...
TAQUITO--
SMALL TACO.
RIGHT.
NINE HOMEMADE SALSAS...
I'M EATING IT
WITH A SPOON IT'S SO GOOD.
AND GUAC GONE WILD
SIX DIFFERENT WAYS.
WE HAVE THE TRADITIONAL,
THE PINEAPPLE
AND THE BLUE CHEESE.
(Eric) BLUE CRAB CHIPOTLE
WITH PICKLED CORN.
WOW.
WE HAVE GOAT CHEESE
AND ROASTED TOMATO.
AND THEN THE ONE WE'RE MAKING
TODAY--SMOKED TROUT AND BACON.
THAT'S GOTTA BE
A NICE ONE.
IT'S GREAT.
AVOCADOS--SMALL BATCH.
THIS IS A SMALL BATCH?
WE GO THROUGH ABOUT SIX,
EIGHT CASES A DAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD KOSHER SALT,
CHOPPED GARLIC, LIME JUICE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA MASH IT.
YOU WANT TO GET IT SOFT...
NICE AND CREAMY.
CREAMY, NO CHUNKS.
(clicking tongue)
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR ONIONS, JALAPEÑO,
FRESH-CHOPPED CILANTRO.
YOU SAY "JALA-PEE-ÑO"
OR "JALA-PAY-ÑO"?
"JALA-PEE-ÑO."
I'M FROM ERIE.
THIS IS OUR
GUACAMOLE TRADICIONAL.
AND WHAT WE DO IS
WE TREAT THIS AS A BASE.
NOW WE'RE ADDING
THE FLAVORS.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOAKED MESQUITE WOOD CHIPS
ON THE STOVETOP--
START IT TO SMOKE,
COME OUT
WITH THE BIG BAD BOY.
WHICH HAS A VENT
AT THE BOTTOM OF IT.
NOW WE'RE ADDING
THE TROUT.
'CAUSE THAT'S
WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
SALT, CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
YOU'RE GONNA SMOKE
THIS BAD BOY.
FIVE MINUTES.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU ROLL
ON THIS ONE.
TAKE A LITTLE MORE
OF OUR GUACAMOLE BASE,
MORE SALT,
CHOPPED BACON,
ROASTED AND DICED
POBLANO CHILIES.
REMOVE THIS, TAKE IT
OUT OF THE SMOKER.
(whistles)
WE'RE GONNA LAY OUR TROUT
ON A SHEET PAN.
OKAY.
FINISH THE TROUT IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
TROUT'S DONE--
NICE AND SMOKY,
FULL OF FLAVOR.
I DIG IT.
PUT IT IN THE REFRIGERATOR
AND LET IT COOL, LET IT FIRM UP.
FLAKE IT ALL
BY HAND...
BY HAND.
AND THEN YOU MIX IT
INTO THE, UH--THE GUAC.
MIX IT INTO
THE GUACAMOLE, RIGHT.
FRESH LIME ON TOP
AND THEN OUR WARM CUMIN CHIPS.
THIS IS TOASTED GROUND
CUMIN SEEDS AND KOSHER SALT.
MMM.
THAT'S THE WAY TO GO
WITH THIS?
THAT'S THE WAY TO GO.
MMM. WHOA. AS SOON AS YOU
PUT IT IN YOUR MOUTH, BOOM,
THERE'S THE SMOKE. THEN YOU GET
SWEET BACON FAT CRUNCH--MMM--
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT COMING
THROUGH IN THE PEPPER,
BACK TO SMOKY--LIME JUICE.
I MEAN, THERE'S, LIKE,
19 THINGS
GOING ON IN MY MOUTH
AT THE SAME TIME. MMM.
OUT OF A GUACAMOLE?
THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
I'D WRITE A BOOK ABOUT GUACAMOLE
IF I WAS YOU,
AND JUST PUT THAT IN THERE--
JUST ONE PAGE.
OPEN IT AND--WHAP--
THERE YOU GO.
JUST ONE PAGE.
SMOKED TROUT PICKUP--
ONE TIME.
IT IS THE MOST DELICIOUS
GUACAMOLE. I MEAN, IT'S AMAZING.
WE HAD THE GOAT CHEESE,
WHICH IS MY FAVORITE.
MY FAVORITE IS
THE PINEAPPLE HABANERO.
I LOVE THE ONE
WITH THE CRAB.
I WANT BOLD,
BIG FLAVORS.
ALL OVER THE MENU.
YOU'RE HAVING...
(woman) THE WILD BOAR.
WITH A PICKLED JALAPEÑO
MUSTARD CREAM SAUCE.
YEAH, IT'S VERY GOOD.
AND FOR THE SUSHI-GRADE
TUNA...
(Eric) CANDIED JALAPEÑO
AND BLOOD ORANGE MARMALADE.
THIS IS PHENOMENAL.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE?
THE MACHACA IS
DEFINITELY THE BEST.
(Eric) IT'S A COFFEE
AND ANCHO-RUBBED BEEF BRISKET.
WE'VE GOT A GREAT SIDE
OF BEEF BRISKET HERE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME COFFEE TO IT.
THIS IS A GUATEMALAN
COFFEE BEAN,
SO, MAN, IS THERE
A TON OF FLAVORS.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
KOSHER SALT VERY LIBERAL,
ANCHO CHILI POWDER.
SO YOU RUB THAT
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
GET ALL THOSE FLAVORS IN THERE
AND FLIP THIS OVER,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME COFFEE TO IT.
ONCE WE DO THE SEASONING
FOR THE SALT,
PUSH THAT IN A LITTLE BIT,
WE'RE GONNA SLAP THIS BAD BOY
FAT SIDE DOWN.
THIS IS GONNA CARAMELIZE
ALL THE FLAVORS,
ALL THE SUGARS,
ALL THAT GOODNESS.
OKAY, SO LOOK
AT THIS THING.
ONCE WE GET A GOOD CHAR
ON THIS, FLIP IT OVER,
SCORE THE OTHER SIDE.
YEAH, IT'S FANTASTIC.
MMM.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT OVER
TO THE CUTTING BOARD.
OH, YOU SHOULD
SMELL THAT.
CUT IT INTO THIRDS. ONCE WE
CUT IT, WE'RE GONNA BRAISE IT.
OKAY. I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
OUT OF YOUR BRAISING.
SPANISH ONION.
ANCHO CHILIES.
BAY LEAF,
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC,
ANCHO POWDER,
VIETNAMESE CINNAMON.
HIGHEST OIL CONTENT--
ADDS THE SWEETNESS.
WHOO.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU SMELL THAT? FANTASTIC.
YEAH, GET THAT PERFUME
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
KOSHER SALT.
IT MAY LOOK LIKE THERE'S
A LOT OF SALT GOING ON,
BUT YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND
THERE'S A TON OF MEAT IN THERE,
AND WITH ALL THOSE FLAVORS,
IT NEEDS IT.
SOME LIME JUICE,
RED WINE VINEGAR,
DRY RED WINE, TOMATO JUICE.
BEFORE WE BRAISE IT, WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE REST OF OUR COFFEE.
COVER IT WITH WATER.
OKAY, SO,
MAD SCIENTIST,
THIS IS ON POINT.
IT WOULD MAKE A GREAT CUP
OF COFFEE, WOULDN'T IT?
HIT IT WITH SOME FOIL, AND HOW
LONG IS IT GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
3 1/2, 4 HOURS
AT 300 DEGREES.
I GOT THE DOOR.
GOOD LOOKIN'.
LOOK AT THAT.
TAKE THIS STUFF OUT.
AND WHAT I'M GONNA DO
IS JUST START SHREDDIN' IT.
COME ON, MOMOCHO,
GIVE ME A LITTLE BIT.
BROTHER...
WHERE YOU GOING
WITH IT NOW?
I'M GONNA GO
BACK TO THE STOVE
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THE JUS.
AND THAT'S HOW WE RECONSTITUTE
THE SHREDDED BEEF.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS ON?
WE ADD CHILI RAJITAS,
WHICH ARE STEWED PEPPERS,
ONIONS, GARLIC, CHILIES,
A LITTLE MEXICAN OREGANO,
HEAVY CREAM.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE MACHACA TO THIS,
GET ALL THAT
GOOD JUICE DOWN.
COTIJA CHEESE.
NICE CHEESE--KIND OF LIKE
PARMESAN, LITTLE BIT SALTY.
A COUPLE LIMES,
GUACAMOLE
AND HOUSE-MADE
TOMATILLO VERDE.
AND THEN WHAT TYPE OF TORTILLAS
ARE GOING WITH THIS?
CORN, BABY. CORN.
I JUST GOTTA GET
A BITE OF THIS BY ITSELF.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
DUDE, THAT IS RIGHTEOUS.
THANKS.
I MEAN, DUDE, THIS IS--
I GOTTA GO BACK IN.
IT'S GOT NICE BITE TO IT.
IT'S NOT TOO HOT,
PHENOMENAL TEXTURE
OUT OF THE BRISKET.
THIS TIME A LITTLE GUAC,
TOMATILLO SALSA--
A REALLY NICE CREAMY,
COOL-IT-DOWN GUAC.
DUDE, YOU KNOCKED
THAT OUT.
AND THE MACHACA.
THE COFFEE AND ANCHO--
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
GUACAMOLE, THE MACHACA--
THIS IS ONE OF A KIND.
IT'S, UH, RIDICULOUS.
YEAH, I WONDER
IF "MOMOCHO"
REALLY MEANS "RIDICULOUS"
IN SPANISH.
(Eric)
SMOKED TROUT UP.
IT'S JUST UNIQUE.
FOOD'S AWESOME.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
WHEN YOU GUYS GET A CHANCE
TO COME TO MOMOCHO'S,
WEAR THE STRETCH PANTS
AND THE MUUMUUS.
CHICKEN UP.
GOOD LUCK, MAN.
I'M VERY HAPPY FOR YOU.
THANKS. I APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
GREAT GUY.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
UP NEXT...
CALAMARI.
WE'RE HEADIN' WEST
TO SANTA CRUZ...
A FAMILY-OWNED
RESTAURANT.
WHERE SCRATCH-MADE
SEAFOOD...
THESE'LL GET DONE
IN A FLOUR DREDGE.
STARTS AT THE DOCK.
TODAY WE'RE ON THE WATER
IN SANTA CRUZ, CALIFORNIA,
TO CHECK OUT A THIRD-GENERATION
SEAFOOD RESTAURANT
THAT STARTED
AS A BAIT AND TACKLE SHOP.
IT'S TIME TO DOCK UP
TO ALDO'S.
CALAMARI.
NICE AND CRISPY--I CAN'T
HELP IT. I JUST WOLF IT DOWN.
GANGSTER ON THE CALAMARI.
OH, YEAH.
THEIR SEAFOOD IS ALWAYS REALLY
FRESH. IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
(man)
PLATING CIOPPINO.
IT'S REALLY SPICY,
FANTASTIC.
UNIQUE SETTING--IT'S
A FAMILY-OWNED RESTAURANT.
MY GRANDFATHER WAS
A FISHERMAN AND A BAKER,
AND THEN IN 1977 HE DECIDED
TO BUILD A RESTAURANT.
THESE DAYS GRANDSON
JOHN'S IN THE KITCHEN.
SEAFOOD PASTA
IN THE WINDOW.
AND HIS DAD MAURO'S
UP THE STREET...
(singing in Italian)
RUNNIN' THEIR BAKERY.
YOU MAKE BREAD HERE. YOU MAKE
PASTA. YOU MAKE EVERYTHING.
ABSOLUTELY.
THIS I GOTTA SEE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
RAVIOLIS HERE.
PASTA MACHINES
ARE FROM ITALY?
RIGHT.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE MY PICTURE WITH IT.
(imitates camera shutter)
WHAT A NICE FEATURE
TO HAVE THIS.
HE'S GONNA MIX IT ALL UP,
AND IT'S GONNA SHEET IT
FOR YOU RIGHT HERE.
EXACTLY.
NICE. ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THAT'S CORRECT.
SEMOLINA.
AND THERE'S THE EGGS.
GRAZIE.
OLIVE OIL.
OKAY.
NUTMEG.
NUTMEG? AND PRECISE
MEASUREMENT ON THIS, SIR?
THAT'S AS PRECISE
AS IT GETS, YOU KNOW?
IF WE NEED ANY MORE,
WE ADD IT.
AND HERE IS SALT
AND ROOM-TEMPERATURE WATER.
JUST PUT A LITTLE BIT IN,
AND YOU'LL CHECK IT
AFTER IT
STARTS RUNNIN'?
RIGHT. OKAY, NOW WE
START BRINGING IT DOWN.
SO THE DOUGH'S DONE--
JUST WET ENOUGH
THAT IT STARTS
TO SQUEEZE TOGETHER.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
START TO SHEET IT.
THAT'S IT. YOU JUST KEEP
ROLLING THAT OUT. PERFECT.
SO IT WENT THROUGH
ITS FIRST PRESS.
THEN WE TAKE IT AND START
PUTTING IT THROUGH THE--
OH, JUST GRAB
THE WHOLE THING.
ATTABOY.
OKAY. YOU KNOW, YOU COULD RUN
SOME LAUNDRY THROUGH THAT.
IN CASE YOU NEED
A SHIRT--EXACTLY.
WE GOT ENOUGH
RICE FLOUR DOWN?
YES, WE DO.
WHO'S IN CHARGE
OF THE RICE FLOUR?
AND THEN WE'LL
LAY IT OUT.
CUT IT?
YEAH. PERFECT.
THERE WE GO. CUT THIS SIDE
OVER HERE, TOO.
THAT'S SOME CRAZY LEGGINGS
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE.
YOU GOTTA RUN
'EM AGAIN, SEE.
OKAY, SO...
NOW WE FOLD IT OVER
AND OPEN IT UP,
SLICE IT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
NOW WE HAVE EVEN AMOUNTS.
EXACTLY. NOW WE ROLL 'EM UP.
JUST LET IT DO IT ON ITS OWN.
THE ROLLERS ARE GONNA
SIT RIGHT HERE?
IT'S JUST HOW YOU PUT
THE TOILET PAPER ON.
WE GOT ANOTHER SET OF ROLLERS
HERE. WE'RE LOADED.
(Guy) AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE FILLING.
(Mauro) WE BOILED...
SPINACH AND SWISS CHARD.
WE SQUEEZE THE WATER OUT.
WE MIX TOGETHER
FOCACCIA BREADCRUMBS.
THEN ONIONS SAUTéED WITH NUTMEG
AND A PINCH OF SALT.
THE ROMANO CHEESE.
PARMESAN.
CORRECT.
OKAY. THIS IS EGGS.
OLIVE OIL.
SO WE PUT IT ALL TOGETHER,
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
(Mauro) THAT'S CORRECT.
LOOK AT THAT MIXTURE. MMM.
OOPS, SOME FELL IN MY MOUTH.
OH, MY GOSH, THAT'S GOOD.
SO THE FILLING GOES
IN THE HOPPER.
THAT'S CORRECT.
ALL RIGHT.
PUSH THE DOUGH INTO THOSE
ROLLERS. THAT'S IT.
CRANK IT DOWN.
PUT THE PRESSURE ON IT,
AND THEN YOU JUST...
NOW IT'LL SELF-FEED.
THAT'S CORRECT.
BEAUTIFUL. LOOK AT THOSE
LITTLE PILLOWS OF MADNESS.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
MARINARA FOR THE RAVIOLIS.
AND ALL THE SAUCES
YOU GUYS MAKE.
RIGHT.
FIRST THE TOMATOES.
CANNED TOMATOES FORTIFIED
WITH THE BASIL.
AND THEN WE ADD
OREGANO, CHILI PEPPER.
THEN WE STIR IT, AND WE'RE
GONNA LET IT COOK.
COVER IT FOR A LITTLE BIT.
THEN WE TURN THE FIRE HERE,
'CAUSE WE DO THE SECOND PART.
OLIO DI OLIVA.
THAT'S WHAT
I WAS GONNA SAY.
SOME GREAT GILROY GARLIC.
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, CHECK THIS OUT--
SOME CAPERS.
BRAVO.
OKAY, THE SALT. LET IT POACH
IN THE OIL A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA DUMP IT IN.
THAT'S CORRECT.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIMMER
AFTER WE PUT
THE GARLIC IN?
A COUPLE HOURS.
THE LONGER IT GOES,
THE BETTER IT IS.
OH, THIS REALLY
LOOKS GOOD.
I WISH WE COULD TRY
SOME OF THIS. OH, MY GOSH.
THIS WAS BAKED
LAST NIGHT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
EXCELLENT, MAN.
AND NOW IT'S TIME
TO COOK THE RAVIOLIS.
APPROXIMATELY
FOUR MINUTES,
AND WHILE THE RAVIOLIS
ARE COOKING,
I'M GONNA ADD A LITTLE MANNA
FROM HEAVEN--MARINARA.
A LITTLE HEAT ON THAT.
ARE THOSE
BAD BOYS DONE?
RIGHT. GET THE WATER
OUT OF IT, AND...
THERE WE ARE.
THOSE BABIES
ARE READY TO GO.
NOW WE NEED A PLATE
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF PARMIGIANO.
AND BUON APPETITO.
MMM. AWESOME.
IF THERE'S A TIME
THAT I REALLY WANT FRESH PASTA,
IT'S WHEN IT COMES
IN A RAVIOLI.
MADE IN THE BAKERY.
THE TWO CHEESES,
THE SWISS CHARD--
THAT'S IMPRESSIVE. MMM.
NEXT TIME I COME THROUGH HERE
WHEN I'M GOING TO HOLLISTER
TO RIDE DIRT BIKES,
I'M GONNA PREORDER
7,000 OR 8,000.
YOU GOT IT.
SERIOUSLY.
RAVIOLI, MARINARA--
UP, PLEASE.
DELICIOUS--
I LOVE THEIR SAUCE.
I'M A SUCKER
FOR A GOOD RAVIOLI.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD
ON THE MENU--
HOMEMADE BREAD
FROM ALDO'S BAKERY.
THE SEAFOOD
IS AWESOME--
THE MUSSELS,
THE CLAMS.
VERY FRESH.
CALAMARI.
THEY CATCH IT OFF THE COAST,
AND THEY BRING IT HERE.
STRAIGHT TO ALDO'S DOCK,
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN PREPPIN' IT
THE SAME WAY
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
WE'RE OUT HERE
CLEANIN' IT EVERY DAY.
WE DO IT THE RIGHT WAY.
TENDER LOVING CARE.
WE KEEP THE BODIES.
SAVE THE TENTACLES--
THESE'LL GET DONE
IN A FLOUR DREDGE
AND FRIED UP.
AND THEN--BOOM--HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON.
AND, OH, MY GOSH, IT'S SOME OF
THE MOST TENDER I'VE EVER HAD.
THE SAME WAY IT'S BEEN DONE
SINCE 1977.
IT'S NICE AND FRESH.
A LOVELY LITTLE CRISPY BATTER--
IT'S ABSOLUTELY SUPERB.
AND A CALAMARI SETUP.
IT'S JUST REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
I HAVE
THE FISHERMAN'S PLATTER.
EVERYTHING IS
JUST EXCELLENT.
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
FROM GRILLED ROCK COD...
THREE ROCK CODS,
ALL DAY.
TO MAHI TACOS...
HUGE BOMB FISH TACOS.
(both) YES.
AND THIS SAN FRANCISCO
CLASSIC...
CIOPPINO--
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
DONE THEIR WAY.
SO--CIOPPINO.
OKAY--BUTTER, A PINCH
OF CHILI PEPPER, GARLIC.
LET IT SIT A FEW SECONDS.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I MISS WORKING SAUTé.
I'LL GET ANY CHANCE
I CAN.
ROCK COD.
THE KEY IS ADDING DIFFERENT
SEAFOODS AT THE RIGHT TIME.
ROCK COD--MORE FIRM,
CAN HANDLE THE TIME.
THEN GO THE SHRIMP.
MUSSELS--
MUSCOLI, MUSCOLI.
AND WE DO CLAM,
MARINARA.
WITH CAPERS.
ABSOLUTELY.
A LITTLE BIT OF VINO.
WHITE WINE.
CALAMARI.
THESE GO DOWN AT THE VERY END,
BECAUSE THE CALAMARI
TAKES VERY LITTLE TIME TO COOK,
AND YOU DON'T WANT IT
TO SIT THERE AND TURN
INTO RUBBER BANDS, CORRECT?
RIGHT.
AND THOSE CRAB LEGS
GONNA MAKE IT DOWN?
WE'LL FIND A PLACE
FOR THEM.
THROW A LID ON THAT.
ABSOLUTELY.
REDUCE THE HEAT.
LET IT SIT FOR A WHILE,
PUT IT ON THE PLATE.
I'M HAVING NIAGARA FALLS
IN MY MOUTH RIGHT NOW.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
LOOK AT THAT.
PUT A LITTLE CRAB ON TOP.
'CAUSE THERE WASN'T ALREADY
FOUR LEGS IN THERE--
WE JUST HAVE TO HAVE MORE.
THE MORE, THE BETTER.
MMM. EVERYTHING IS NICE
AND TENDER.
YOU CAN TASTE THE SEAFOOD
INSIDE OF THE SAUCE.
GOT A BIG OLD PIECE
OF CALAMARI. OH, MAN.
YOU SO WISH YOU COULD
TRY THIS RIGHT NOW.
GREAT FLAVOR--
ALL AROUND, IT'S PERFECT.
IT'S REALLY SPICY,
SEAFOOD IS A GOOD MIX.
TO BE ABLE
TO COME HERE,
ENJOY THE BEAUTY AND HAVE
GOOD FOOD--THAT'S SPECIAL.
YOU HAVE TO COME HERE--
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL SETTING
IN THE WORLD,
AND YOU GET GREAT FOOD.
HEY, WHAT IS THAT
OVER THERE?
WHICH ONE?
OH, HO HO HO.
OH, HO,
HE GOT ME THAT TIME.
NEXT STOP...
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
WE'RE HEADIN' EAST
TO WESTERN NEW YORK...
IT'S HOMEMADE,
AND IT'S FABULOUS.
FOR COMFORT FOOD...
COULD YOU SLOW DOWN?
I'M OUT OF BREATH.
TO BEAT THE CLOCK.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYBODY
MAKE SHEPHERD'S PIE IN JUST,
LIKE, RECORD TIME.
SO I'M CRUISIN' DOWN
HIGHWAY 16
BETWEEN OLEAN
AND BUFFALO, NEW YORK,
KIND OF IN THE CHAFFEE AREA,
YOU KNOW,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN I START
HEARIN' THIS STUFF IN MY HEAD.
(Guy echoing) IF YOU COOK IT,
THEY WILL COME.
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
SO I HAVE TO PULL OVER.
I HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT IS GOING ON.
IS THIS HEAVEN?
NO, MAN,
THIS IS EARL'S.
GOT A HAM STEAK DINNER.
FAMOUS PLACE
AROUND HERE.
HERE YOU GO.
FOOD'S ALWAYS GREAT.
IT'S HOMEMADE,
AND IT'S FABULOUS.
IT'S JUST LIKE IT WAS
IN THE OLD DAYS.
THEY WERE BALING HAY RIGHT HERE
WHEN I BOUGHT THE LAND.
BUT EARL NORTHRUP
WASN'T PLANNIN' ON FARMING.
HE PUT UP A DRIVE-IN
AND TURNED IT
INTO A SIT-DOWN
RESTAURANT.
ENJOY.
WE FURNISH A LOT OF GOOD EATS,
BUT SIMPLE.
I GOT A CHEDDAR MELT.
CRANKED OUT THESE DAYS
BY HEAD CHEF
BARRY KELLER.
CHICKEN à LA KING.
ALL THE THINGS IN IT
MAKES IT JUST GREAT.
HOT MEAT LOAF.
AND GET THIS--THEY'RE SERVING
UP A BRITISH CLASSIC.
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
IS SHEPHERD'S PIE
BIG HERE?
YES, SIR,
AND THEY'LL SELL OUT.
SHEPHERD'S PIE
IS GREAT.
HOW DO WE GET GOING?
OKAY, FIRST THING I'M GONNA DO
IS THROW THE MEAT INTO HERE.
SOME 80/20?
YEP. AND THEN WE GOTTA
GRIND UP SOME BREADCRUMBS.
DAY-OLD HAMBURGER BUNS?
NO, FRESH.
FRESH, OF COURSE.
AND WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
MINE.
REALLY? WHERE DID YOU
LEARN THIS ONE?
MY MOM.
SHE USED TO MAKE
THIS A LOT.
AND YOU GET THAT TO WHERE
IT'S REAL NICE AND FINE,
NO BIG LUMPS,
DUMP IT RIGHT ON TOP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME ONIONS HERE TO IT.
OKAY.
ONE EGG FOR EACH POUND
OF GROUND BEEF.
WE GOT TEN.
YOU ARE A MACHINE, DUDE.
NOW WE GOT SOME SALT
AND A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER
SEEN ANYBODY MAKE...
BLACK PEPPER.
SHEPHERD'S PIE IN JUST,
LIKE, RECORD TIME.
AND...
AND THIS IS
WORCESTERSHIRE.
(whistles)
AND THEN WE JUST MIX
ALL THAT UP.
DO YOU ALWAYS COOK
THIS FAST?
YEP, ALWAYS.
WE HAVE MADE
THIS ENTIRE MIXTURE
WITHIN PROBABLY
ABOUT 60 SECONDS.
THERE'S BEEN A LITTLE DELAY,
'CAUSE I'VE TALKED.
WE'RE READY.
OKAY. COULD YOU SLOW DOWN?
I'M OUT OF BREATH.
(laughing)
WE'LL PUT SOME ALUMINUM FOIL
ON THERE AND PUT IT IN THE OVEN
AND LET HER GO.
WAS THAT ONE WORD?
YEP.
THAT WAS 1 WORD,
17 HYPHENS.
OKAY, SO 350 FOR 2 HOURS.
OKAY, CRACK HER OPEN.
IT LOOKS A LITTLE
MEAT LOAFY-ISH.
YEAH.
IS THAT A WORD,
"MEAT LOAFY-ISH"?
COULD BE.
OKAY.
MAKE THE BROWN GRAVY
FOR THE SHEPHERD'S PIE
FOR THE SHEPHERD'S PIE.
MAKE A ROUX.
NOW YOU ADD
SOME KITCHEN BOUQUET,
SO YOU CAN GIVE IT SOME COLOR
AND A LITTLE FLAVOR.
TAKE THE ROUX AND ADD IT
TO THE BEEF STOCK
AND PUT IT ON TOP.
AND THEN OUR CORN WILL GO
RIGHT IN ON TOP OF IT.
THEN MASHED POTATOES WILL
JUST GO ON TOP OF THAT.
AND WHAT YOU GOT
IN THOSE MASHED?
JUST PEPPER AND A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC, A POUND OF BUTTER.
OH, OKAY.
NOW HOW LONG WILL THIS
GO BACK IN THE OVEN FOR?
OH, JUST ABOUT
TEN MINUTES.
JUST TO BROWN THOSE
MASHED POTATOES UP ON TOP?
YOU GOT IT.
OKAY, LOOKS LIKE CULINARY
QUICKSAND IN FLAVOR TOWN.
OH, YEAH.
CAN YOU SEE THE STEAM?
MMM, OH, THAT'S GOOD.
YOU GET ALL THAT WORCESTERSHIRE
DOWN IN THAT MEAT,
AND THEN YOU GET THAT NICE,
LITTLE SWEET CORN,
THEN YOU GET THAT TWICE-BAKED
MASHED POTATO THING GOING ON.
YEAH, I CAN FEEL IT STICKIN'
TO MY RIB RIGHT NOW.
IT'S SIMPLE BUT PACKED
WITH FLAVOR.
YOU DID THAT RIGHT, MAN.
THE SHEPHERD'S PIE
IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
AND THE PRICES ARE RIGHT.
HOW MUCH IS THIS?
(Barry) $6.25.
DID EARL FORGET THE ECONOMY
AND INFLATION WENT ON?
THAT'S THE WAY EARL'S
ALWAYS DONE IT.
(woman) THERE YOU GO.
IT'S A HOMETOWN RESTAURANT.
THIS IS
VERY COMFORTABLE.
YOU ALWAYS SIT
RIGHT HERE?
PRETTY MUCH, YEAH.
EARL'S IS A TRADITION.
AND SO IS THE MENU...
MM-MMM.
I'VE PROBABLY HAD
ABOUT EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
FROM THE POT ROAST
SANDWICH...
IT'S REALLY TENDER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
CHOCOLATE-PEANUT BUTTER.
TO 15 KINDS
OF HOMEMADE PIE...
I'M HOOKED
ON THE PIE.
AND THIS ONE...
STUFFED PORK CHOPS.
STUFFED THE EARL'S WAY,
WHICH BRINGS US BACK
TO THOSE BURGER BUNS.
OH, AM I DOING
ALL THE WORK?
I'M--JUST 'CAUSE
I HAND IT OFF...
OKAY.
THINK YOU'RE CHANGIN'
ALL THE TIRES
ON THIS SPEEDY
CULINARY RACETRACK.
OKAY, SOME BLACK PEPPER,
POULTRY SEASONING.
SAGE?
YOU GOT IT.
CELERY.
HANDFULS OF CELERY HERE.
ALL THE ONIONS?
YEAH.
AND WE GOT SIX EGGS.
OKAY.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
YEP.
OH, THAT'S JUST A TOUCH.
YEAH.
AND WE'LL START STUFFING.
PUT A LOT RIGHT INSIDE
THAT POCKET THERE.
RIGHT IN LIKE THAT.
AND THEN A LITTLE EXTRA,
TILL IT FLOWS OUT.
JUST RIGHT ON TOP.
THAT'S A BIG CHOP, TOO.
12 OUNCES.
(whistles) LOOK
AT THE SIZE OF THAT THING.
EVERYTHING IS BIG
AT EARL'S.
SO A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK
IN THERE NOW?
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK
RIGHT ALL IN THERE.
OVER THE TOP OF IT OR--
NO, YOU DON'T WANT TO DO THAT.
NO, RIGHT WHERE
THERE'S METAL. GOOD.
A LITTLE SPRINKLE OF ROSEMARY
ON TOP OF EACH ONE.
ABSOLUTELY.
(groans) I GOT SO EXCITED.
I WAS TRYING TO DO IT FAST.
HOW IS THAT--NICE?
BEAUTEOUS. NOW WE'LL
PUT A BLANKET ON THERE.
35 MINUTES, 350.
YOU GOT IT.
READY TO GO, BROTHER?
YES.
SCREAMIN' AND STEAMIN'.
HELP YOURSELF.
EENY, MINY, MINY--
THOSE THREE.
YEAH?
AND THIS IS REALLY
A NORMAL PORTION?
IT'S A NORMAL PORTION.
MMM. DELICIOUS. I MEAN,
THAT'S COMFORT FOOD 101.
IT'S AN ENORMOUS PORK CHOP.
IT'S NOT DRIED OUT,
SUPER FLAVORFUL STUFFING,
SIMPLE. MMM.
WELL, IN FOUR BITES,
I'M FULL.
NICE JOB, BUDDY,
REALLY.
STUFFED PORK CHOP.
A LOT OF ROSEMARY--
IT WAS GOOD.
JUST DOWN HOME.
THIS IS
A HOT MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
IT'S GOOD FOOD.
RIGHT HERE.
IT'S SUCH A TRADITION.
OH, YES, IT IS.
CHICKEN à LA KING.
STRAIGHT OUT
OF 1950, 1960.
SO WE'RE HEADIN' BACK
IN TIME WHEN WE COME BACK.
THAT'S CRAZY.
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
EARL'S DRIVE-IN
IN CHAFFEE, NEW YORK...
ENJOY.
HAS BEEN A LOCAL FAVORITE
SINCE THE '50s.
I GOT
A TWO-PIECE WHITE.
AND HEAD CHEF BARRY KELLER
HAS BEEN CRANKIN' OUT
THE COMFORT FOOD
FOR NEARLY 15 YEARS...
STUFFED PORK CHOP.
FROM PORK CHOPS TO MEAT LOAF
TO THIS ONE...
CHICKEN à LA KING.
THAT'S HARD TO COME BY.
I DON'T EVEN REMEMBER THE LAST
TIME I HAD CHICKEN à LA KING.
A CREAMY SAUCE
AND LOTS OF VEGGIES.
AND THESE GUYS ARE SERVIN' IT
OVER SCRATCH-MADE BISCUITS.
OH, LOOK AT THESE BAD BOYS--
LIGHT AND FLUFFY.
THAT'S PRETTY
OLD SCHOOL.
YEAH.
IT'S GOOD.
HOW ARE WE
GETTIN' STARTED?
WE TAKE A POUND
OF BUTTER.
I'M ALWAYS FOND
OF A POUND OF BUTTER.
LET THE BUTTER MELT DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR CELERY
INTO THE BUTTER.
SO MAKE A LITTLE
MIREPOIX HERE.
RIGHT.
THEN CARROTS NEXT.
GREEN BELL PEPPERS
BEEN MINCED DOWN
AND SOME ONIONS--OKAY.
BLACK PEPPER
AND POULTRY SEASONING.
JUST KINDA SWEAT THOSE OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
THROW A COVER ON THAT
AND LET HER SIMMER DOWN.
ALL RIGHT, SO WHILE THAT'S
COOKIN', WE START THE CHICKEN?
RIGHT.
OKAY.
WE GOT THAT IN A SEPARATE POT.
PUT THE CHICKEN IN.
ADD CHICKEN STOCK AND LET
THAT BOIL OFF UNTIL IT'S DONE.
SO NOW THE VEGGIES
ARE ALL SWEATED?
RIGHT.
NOW HOW MUCH FLOUR
YOU WANT?
ABOUT HALF A BUCKET.
ABOUT 3 CUPS.
THAT GOOD?
THERE YOU GO.
AND MIX THAT UP A LITTLE
AND LET IT GET UP TO
THE CONSISTENCY THAT WE WANT IT.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD THAT
CHICKEN STOCK RIGHT INTO THERE.
DROP INTO THE BUCKET,
CAP'N.
OH, SO YOU'RE REALLY--
THIS IS GONNA BE TIGHT.
THAT'S HOW WE WANT IT.
NOW WE WANT TO TAKE
AND ADD PEAS TO THAT.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS CREAM
OF MUSHROOM.
CREAM OF MUSHROOM SOUP.
OH, HO HO.
MIX HER UP SOME MORE.
SO YOU DON'T WANT TO BREAK
THOSE LITTLE PEAS UP.
(English accent)
BE GENTLE, PEAS.
THE LITTLE PETITE PEAS.
(normal voice)
ADD OUR CHICKEN TO HER,
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
AND THAT'S
CHICKEN à LA KING, HUH?
CHICKEN à LA KING.
BADA BING,
PUT IT OVER TOP OF
THE BUTTERMILK BISCUITS.
THIS A PRETTY
POPULAR ITEM HERE?
WE SELL A LOT OF THIS
HERE EVERY DAY.
WHERE CAN YOU GET
THAT MUCH FOOD FOR $4?
THAT'S NOT 4 BUCKS.
$4.99.
SERIOUSLY?
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THAT'S GREAT--
NICE CHUNKS OF CHICKEN,
CREAMY AS CAN BE, TASTES LIKE
A CHICKEN POTPIE EXPLODED,
AND THE BISCUIT'S SUPER NICE
AND TENDER AND FLAKY.
THAT'S JUST DOWN-HOME
GOOD COMFORT FOOD, BROTHER.
THAT'S CRAZY. MMM.
THAT'S WHAT WE
LIKE TO DO HERE.
WE GOT
A CHICKEN à LA KING.
RIGHT HERE.
THE CHICKEN'S TENDER,
CREAM WITH THE VEGETABLES--
OH, YOU JUST CAN'T
BEAT IT.
ENJOY.
THERE IS
VERY MEMORABLE FOOD. MMM.
YOU GOTTA GO TO EARL'S.
MM-MMM.
THE EXPERIENCE
IS WORTH THE TRIP.
(Guy) TIME FORGOT
THIS PLACE.
IT'S STRAIGHT OUT OF 1950,
1960--JUST RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S HOW YOUR GRANDMA
WOULD MAKE IT, YOU KNOW?
YEAH.
AGAIN, NICE JOB.
SO I TOLD YOU, IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DID YOU JUST SEE
GUY DOUBLE-DIP?
OH, YOU THINK THAT'S
INTERESTING? WATCH THIS.
HOW WAS THAT ONE?