HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
READY FOR A TASTE?
(Guy) THIS TRIP,
COMFORT FOOD CLASSICS.
THAT IS DOWN-HOME
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
IN SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA...
ONE OF THE BEST-KEPT SECRETS.
AN AUTO REPAIR SHOP
TURNED BURGER JOINT...
TWO BURGERS UP.
WHERE SCRATCH COOKIN'...
DO YOU TASTE IT NOW?
WE TASTE IT NOW.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
EVEN INCLUDES THE KETCHUP.
LOOK HOW THICK IT IS.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
IN CHARLOTTE...
FANTASTIC, WHOLESOME,
GOOD FOOD.
A FUNKY JOINT...
ORDER UP.
DOING SOUTHERN COMFORT...
CHICKEN
AND BLACK BEAN BURRITO.
THEIR WAY.
SWEET POTATOES ARE GOING
IN THE BURRITO?
SOUTHERN GOES MEXICO.
AND IN PROVIDENCE...
WHO'S GOT
THE JOHNNYCAKES?
A DINER REBORN...
THE FOOD IS GREAT.
DOING THE RHODE ISLAND
CLASSICS...
BOWL WITH CHOWDER.
MY WIFE LORI GREW UP ON.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE CHOWDER?
THE CHOWDER IS FABULOUS.
THE FLAVOR'S REAL.
MMM.
TAKE A QUART TO GO?
(laughing)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE FUNNY
THINGS ABOUT TRIPLE "D"
IS HOW WE FIND THESE TRENDS.
LIKE, UH, CHECK THIS OUT.
PLACES THAT WERE ONCE GARAGES
AND THEN TURNED
INTO RESTAURANTS.
WELL, YOU REMEMBER MOgridder's
IN THE BRONX
WHERE YOU CAN GET AN OIL CHANGE
AND A RACK OF RIBS.
WELL, THEN THERE'S GEORGIA'S
GREEK RESTAURANT AND DELI
IN SEATTLE
WHERE THEY DID THAT
CRAZY FLAMING CHEESE.
AND HERE IN SAN JOSE,
AT NAGLEE PARK GARAGE,
WHERE THIS JOINT IS SMALL,
BUT I HEAR THE FLAVOR'S BIG.
A NICE JUICY PIECE
OF LEG OF LAMB.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
MAPLE LACQUERED
CURRY CHICKEN.
UNUSUAL COMBINATION,
BUT IT REALLY WORKS.
TWO BURGERS UP.
GRILLED TROUT.
LOUIS DOES IT PERFECT.
THAT'D BE LONG-TIME RESTAURANT
DUDE LOUIS SILVA...
(Louis) POLLY, BURGERS.
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT
WITH A COUPLE OF BUDDIES
A FEW YEARS BACK,
TURNING THIS PIT STOP
INTO A GRUB STOP.
(Louis) THE LEEK & SAUSAGE BAKE.
I WANTED TO KEEP IT SIMPLE,
CLEAN AND VERY FRESH.
CLAM AND ASPARAGUS
AND FENNEL.
FRESH.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD HERE.
I CANNOT FIND A HAMBURGER
LIKE THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE
IN SAN JOSE.
HE MAKES HIS OWN BARBECUE SAUCE,
AND HE MAKES HIS OWN KETCHUP.
(man) THANK YOU.
THIS IS CALLED
THE GARAGE KETCHUP.
DICED TOMATOES.
ALL THAT TOMATO PASTE?
ALL THIS TOMATO PASTE.
NOW YOU KNOW THAT--
YOU KNOW--
YOU WANT TO HOLD THAT
FOR ME?
YEAH, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
SOUS-CHEF-ING ALREADY.
SOME CINNAMON.
NOW ARE WE GONNA
PURéE THIS LATER?
NO, NO, IT'S CHUNKY.
IF SOMEBODY FINDS
THE CINNAMON STICK,
THEY WIN A...
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THEY WIN
A STUFFED BEAR?
THEY'LL WIN
SOME CINNAMON.
BAY LEAF. AND THEY WIN
BAY LEAF, TOO.
IT'S GONNA BE
THAT KIND OF DAY.
AND SOME CLOVES.
OKAY, THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME GARLIC.
AND WE'RE CLOSE
TO GILROY.
YEAH, WE ARE. SOME ONIONS
AND VINEGAR APPLE CIDER.
VINEGAR APPLE CIDER
OR APPLE CIDER VINEGAR?
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
(laughs)
THEN WE GOT SOME
SYRUP CORN.
SOME SYRUP CORN.
SOME MOLASSES.
I LOVE THIS PRECISE
MEASURING TECHNIQUE.
YEAH. IT'S A GARAGE.
AND A LITTLE
WORCESTERSHIRE.
HOW DID YOU COME UP
WITH THIS RECIPE?
I JUST--
PLAYING AROUND,
AND I WAS LOOKING
FOR THE RIGHT FLAVORS,
AND THIS IS WHAT
I CAME UP WITH.
BOIL IT FOR ABOUT AN HOUR,
LET IT COOL, AND THAT'S IT.
AND IT GOT THICKER.
DO YOU TASTE IT NOW?
OH, YOU DO? OH,
HE DIDN'T ANSWER, DID HE?
DO YOU TASTE IT NOW?
WE TASTE IT NOW.
OH, THAT'S GOOD. I MEAN,
LOOK HOW THICK IT IS.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
DEFINITELY GET SOME OF THAT
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
IT'S GOT SOME CHUNKS IN IT.
IT'S GOT SOME MEAT TO IT.
AND WHAT DOES IT
COME WITH?
WHATEVER YOU WANT IT
TO COME WITH.
ALL OF MY FAVORITES.
WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A BURGER.
WHAT SIZE?
10 TO 11 OUNCES.
MY HANDS ARE A SCALE.
MINE ARE WEAPONS.
YEAH.
SO WE'LL JUST KIND OF
MOLD IT OUT,
THROW SOME SALT
AND PEPPER ON THAT.
THIS IS OUR GRILL.
IT GOES ON THERE.
LET ME GUESS THEN.
THEN THIS IS THE FRYER.
THAT'S THE FRYER. SO NOW WE'RE
GONNA GRAB SOME FRIES HERE.
AND WE PRE-BLANCH THEM.
YOU HIT THOSE
IN REGULAR CANOLA OIL.
THEN ABOUT, WHAT,
350, 325?
YEAH.
AND WHAT HAPPENS IF WE HAVE
MORE THAN FOUR BURGERS?
WE JUST MAKE IT JIVE.
YOU JUST MAKE IT WORK?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO YOU'RE CROSS-CHECKING
A LITTLE BIT THERE.
YEAH, GIVE 'EM A LITTLE
DIAMOND ACTION GOING.
POPPY SEED
AND ONION ROLL.
YOU SHOULD SMELL--
HERE, SMELL.
I'M GONNA CHECK
MY POTATOES OVER HERE.
NICE COLOR. WE'RE GONNA
PULL THEM OUT RIGHT NOW.
LOOK AT THIS BURGER, SERIOUSLY.
AAH! IT'S HOT.
LOOK AT THAT JUICE
COMING OUT OF THAT.
STEAM MY FINGER OFF.
OKAY, SO I'M GONNA JUST TOAST
THE BREAD A LITTLE BIT.
SEE, AND I LIKE THAT. I DON'T
THINK YOU NEED THE BUTTER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE BLUE CHEESE ON THAT.
THROW SOME MAYONNAISE ON THERE
THAT WE MAKE HERE.
SOME MAYONNAISE. YOU MAKE
THE MAYONNAISE, ALSO?
YEAH, WE MAKE
THE MAYONNAISE.
AT THE GE-RAGE.
THE BURGER'S DONE.
TOSS 'EM WITH A LITTLE PARSLEY,
SALT AND PEPPER.
I GOTTA TRY
THIS KETCHUP FIRST.
MMM. YOU KNOW WHAT
I REALLY PICK UP?
THE NOTE OF THE CINNAMON
AND THE CLOVE.
YEAH.
THAT IS GOOD KETCHUP.
THANK YOU.
LOOK AT THE JUICE JUST RUNNING
OUT OF THIS. WATCH.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THAT'S A GOOD BURGER,
MAN.
I THINK THE MAYONNAISE
IS A NICE LITTLE KICK.
NOW I'LL TRY A BITE
WITH SOME KETCHUP.
MMM.
PAN-FORMED 80/20 ANGUS
WITH HOMEMADE KETCHUP
AND HOMEMADE MAYONNAISE.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
MMM.
YOU HAVE TO DUNK IT.
GOOD JOB. MMM.
YOU GOT KETCHUP
FOR THE BURGERS?
THE OUTSIDE IS JUST CHARRED,
AND THE INSIDE
IS PERFECTLY RARE.
HOMEMADE KETCHUP.
OH, YEAH.
IT SETS IT OFF JUST RIGHT.
CHICKEN UP.
ANYTHING YOU ORDER
IS GONNA BE GREAT.
ANY WAY YOU ORDER IT.
EVERYTHING'S à LA CARTE.
ASPARAGUS AND STEAK.
(Louis) PICK UP A LEG OF LAMB
WITH LEEKS AND CARROTS.
SO I HAVE THE TROUT,
TWO ASPARAGUS AND FENNEL.
FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
BRUSSELS SPROUTS?
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
I LOVE THE BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE DOING?
WE'RE MAKING BRUSSELS SPROUTS?
YES, WE ARE.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
BAY LEAF, SAGE, FRESH.
LET ME GUESS, YOU'RE GROWING
THE SAGE OUT BACK?
UH, ACTUALLY,
YEAH, WE ARE.
DO YOU WANT TO GO SEE IT?
NO, I TRUST YOU.
SLICED LEMON. AND WE DO HAVE
A LEMON TREE IN THE BACK.
I DIDN'T
SEE THE PASTURE,
NOR THE GOAT
WHERE YOU MAKE THE CHEESE.
YOU KNOW,
I DON'T DO THAT YET.
THROW SOME GARLIC IN THERE,
ADD SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
THROW IN SOME
BRUSSELS SPROUTS IN HERE.
THE LITTLE BOWL
THAT DOES EVERYTHING.
YEAH.
SMALL PLACE, SMALL BOWL.
TOSS 'EM, TOSS 'EM,
TOSS 'EM, TOSS 'EM.
SO A NICE
LITTLE COATING ON 'EM.
THEN WE'LL BRING OVER
OUR FOIL.
PARCHMENT PAPER.
I LIKE THE LEMON COMPONENT.
NEVER THOUGHT OF THAT ONE.
KIND OF LIKE WE'RE
DOING SOME FISH--
A LITTLE PAPILLOTE.
EXACTLY.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA SLOW-ROAST AT?
WHEN I SMELL 'EM,
I KNOW THEY'RE DONE.
YOU SMELL-O-TEST IT?
YEAH.
FOR THOSE OF US THAT
HAVEN'T BEEN TRAINED
AT LE CORDON BLEU
DE BLOODHOUND,
UH, HOW LONG WOULD
THEY GO IN LE MINUTES?
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
SAY 30 MINUTES.
350?
350.
REALLY?
SO THEY'RE GONNA CRANK?
CAN YOU SMELL
BRUSSELS SPROUTS?
I SMELL
BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
MY NEW FAVORITE WAY
TO DO BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
OPEN 'EM WITH CAUTION
BECAUSE YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
SOME STEAM COMING OUT.
WOW, MAN.
THAT'S AMAZING. YOU COULD
SERVE THEM JUST LIKE THAT.
YEAH.
YOU'RE GONNA
LET 'EM COOL DOWN.
IF SOMEONE ORDERS 'EM,
HOW DO YOU PREPARE 'EM?
WE GOT A HOT PAN.
THAT'S ONE ORDER?
ONE ORDER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME BUTTER IN THERE,
GONNA THROW SOME BACON IN
THERE--IN A LITTLE MORE BACON.
YEAH, YEAH.
SALT AND PEPPER AND THEN
A LITTLE BIT OF STOCK.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK?
YEAH.
AND YOU MAKE
THAT STOCK YOURSELF?
YEAH.
ONCE THE BUBBLES ARE GETTING
A LITTLE BIGGER THERE,
THEY'LL BE READY.
WHAT WAS THAT?
I'M LOOKING
AT THE BUBBLES,
AND WHEN THEY START KIND OF--
SEE HOW THEY'RE--
SO WE'RE NOT USING
THE BLOODHOUND ON THIS ONE?
NO.
WE'RE USING
THE EAGLE EYE.
YEAH.
IT'S NOT TIMING.
IT'S BUBBLE SIZE.
JUST KNOW THY BUBBLE?
KNOW THE BUBBLE.
THAT'S A MEAL IN ITSELF.
DOES IT LOOK HOT? THAT'S NOT
A FOG MACHINE COMING OFF THERE.
EXCELLENT, MAN.
THIS IS FOR PEOPLE
THAT THINK THEY DON'T
LIKE BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
TENDER, BUT NOT SO DONE
THAT IT'S MUSHY.
THAT IS GREAT.
THE BUBBLE METHOD WORKS.
THEY'RE HOT.
HERE'S YOUR LEG OF LAMB
AND YOUR BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
CRUNCHY, A NICE LITTLE
CARAMELIZED ON THE OUTSIDE.
GOT BACON IN HERE.
LOU, HALF A CHICKEN.
HALF A CHICKEN.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST-KEPT
SECRETS IN SAN JOSE.
PICK UP TWO BURGERS.
HE'S THE REAL DEAL.
I'M JUST TRYING TO, HOPEFULLY,
TOUCH SOME PEOPLE
AND MAKE PEOPLE HAPPY.
HI, SWEETHEART.
HOW ARE YOU?
THAT'S AWESOME.
GOOD JOB, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
REALLY NICE.
UP NEXT...
MEAT LOAF UP.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CHARLOTTE...
IT'S JUST GREAT
HOME COOKING.
FOR SOUTHERN COMFORT...
(woman) LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE DONE.
(Guy) THAT'S A LOT
OF SALMON PATTY.
IT IS.
DONE THEIR WAY.
HERE'S
WHAT I DIG ABOUT IT.
THERE'S A LOT OF CRUNCH
ON THAT CAKE.
I'M HERE
IN CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA.
NOW ANY TIME I ROLL INTO TOWN,
I GOTTA COME BY AND SEE MY BUDDY
GREG AT THE PENGUIN DRIVE-IN.
YOU REMEMBER, DEEP-FRIED
PICKLES, PIMENTO CHEESE,
THE FULL-BLOWN HEMI.
BUT BEFORE I GO IN THERE,
I GOTTA GO ABOUT 100 YARDS
DOWN THE WAY HERE
AND CHECK OUT ANOTHER JOINT
FOR TRIPLE "D."
THESE FOLKS ARE SERVING UP
SOME SOUTHERN CLASSICS.
THIS IS DISH.
MEAT LOAF UP.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S LIKE GOING TO GRANDMA'S.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
THEY'RE FANTASTIC.
BLACK-EYED PEAS.
ALL THE PLATES COME
WITH A DEVILED EGG
AND THE BISCUIT,
AS WELL.
IT'S JUST GREAT HOME-COOKED
SOUTHERN-STYLE FOOD.
MMM.
IN A JOINT RUN BY A COUPLE
OF FORMER NIGHTCLUB OWNERS...
HEY, SWEETIES.
ORIGINALLY,
IT WAS MY IDEA.
PENNY CRAVER
AND MAGGIE STUBBS...
LET'S HEAD ON BACK.
WHO DECIDED IT WAS TIME
TO SERVE UP MORE THAN BEER.
WE ALL GREW UP EATING GOOD
SOUTHERN HOME COOKING.
MAC AND CHEESE, TABLE EIGHT.
THE KIND THAT BROUGHT HEAD COOK
KIRSTIE FLOYD TO THE SOUTH...
ORDER UP.
AFTER COOKING IN EUROPE
AND ALL OVER THE U.S.
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
MOST POPULAR ITEM
ON THE MENU.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
OHH.
THAT'S ALL I EVER GET.
SERIOUSLY?
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER
GOTTEN ANYTHING ELSE.
SOUTHERN CLASSIC,
AND THEY DO IT VERY WELL HERE.
IT REMINDS ME
OF WHEN I WAS A KID.
THE DISH I WOULD ALWAYS LOOK
FORWARD TO MY DAD WOULD MAKE
WOULD BE CHICKEN
AND DUMPLINGS.
TELL ME ABOUT
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
OKAY.
START OFF
WITH THE RAW BIRD,
BASTE IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER,
SOME SALT AND PEPPER MIX
AND PUT IT RIGHT INTO THE OVEN.
AND THEN 350 DEGREES--
350 DEGREES,
55 MINUTES.
55 MINUTES. ROAST IT
TO GIVE THE ROASTING FLAVOR
TO GET SOME OF THAT FLAVOR
OUT OF THE BONES INTO THE MEAT.
MM-HMM.
SO THE BIRD'S
COOLED DOWN NOW,
POURED OFF THE JUICES
FOR THE STOCK,
AND NOW IT'S TIME
TO SHRED-IFY?
SHRED-IFY.
DO YOU EVER GROWL
WHEN YOU DO IT?
IT DEPENDS ON THE DAY.
AFTER WE SEPARATE ALL THE
CHICKEN, WE'LL PUT THAT ASIDE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
MAKING THE STOCK.
AND THE BONE AND THE SKIN, WHICH
WE PULLED FROM THE CHICKEN.
IT'S ABOUT TWO PITCHERS
OF WATER AND THE BROTH.
SOME OF THE FAT.
OH, YEAH.
THE GOOD STUFF.
SOME DICED
WHITE ONION...
(whistles)
PEPPER,
A LOT OF PEPPER...
GENEROUS.
SOME CELERY SALT, 'CAUSE
THAT'S ALWAYS REALLY GOOD
TO PULL
THE CHICKEN FLAVOR OUT.
GRANULATED GARLIC
AND GRANULATED ONION, AS WELL.
HOW LONG IS IT GONNA
BOIL FOR?
WE'LL BOIL IT ABOUT
10, 15 MINUTES.
COOL IT JUST A TINY BIT
SO IT'S MANAGEABLE.
STRAIN IT.
STRAIN IT OUT,
PUT IT BACK INTO THE POT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GET
INTO MAKING THE DUMPLINGS.
THE DUMPLINGS.
(sighs)
ALL RIGHTY.
START WITH FLOUR,
FOUR EGGS
AND 1/2 A POUND
OF MELTED BUTTER.
MIX IT UP.
OKAY. NOW FORM IT.
ALL RIGHT. FLOUR.
JUST ROLL IT OUT
ABOUT A 1/4 INCH.
DON'T WANT 'EM TOO THIN 'CAUSE
THEY TEND TO DISINTEGRATE
WHEN YOU GET 'EM
INTO THE HOT LIQUID.
AND WE DON'T WANT THAT.
YOU WANT 'EM
TO PUFF UP.
PUFF UP.
JUST CUT 'EM
IN LITTLE SQUARES.
OH, LOOK AT HER DOING IT
THE BACKWARDS WAY.
SHOW-OFF.
(laughing)
AND THERE WE GO.
YOU MADE IT
LOOK SO EASY.
OH, THANKS.
I TRY.
HANDMADE AT THE DISH.
WE'LL HAVE ALL THESE
READY TO GO. GO TIME.
READY TO GO.
ADD OUR
ALREADY PULLED CHICKEN.
WE GOT WHITE AND DARK
IN THERE?
OH, YEAH. I'M GONNA
ADD OUR DUMPLINGS.
YOU DON'T WANT TO DUMP 'EM
ALL AT ONE TIME
'CAUSE THEY TIGHTEN UP AS SOON
AS THEY HIT THAT HOT WATER,
AND THEN YOU GOT YOURSELF
THIS BALL.
A BIG,
MASSIVE DUMPLING.
WE KEEP THEM SEPARATED.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD A BASIC
ROUX, JUST BUTTER AND FLOUR.
BUT YOU'RE ALSO GONNA
GET SOME THICKENER
JUST COMING OUT OF THAT
DUMPLING DOUGH.
AND LET IT GO FOR ABOUT 30
MINUTES TO COOK THOSE DUMPLINGS?
ABSOLUTELY.
READY FOR A TASTE?
(scoffs)
LOOK AT ALL THE CHICKEN.
MY MOUTH IS ALREADY
STARTING TO WATER.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE AND THICK.
AND LOOK AT THAT DUMPLING
RIGHT THERE.
MMM. AWESOME,
REALLY AWESOME.
EASIER IF I GET IT UP
TO THE...
THERE YOU GO.
WE GOT A SUPER-TENDER
DUMPLING,
AND I LIKE THE FACT
THAT YOU ROASTED THE CHICKEN,
SO IT'S GOT
REAL CHICKEN FLAVOR.
WE GOT HOMEMADE
CHICKEN STOCK WITH ROUX,
VERY SIMPLY SEASONED.
THAT IS DOWN-HOME
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
WONDERFUL.
MMM. CUT.
(slurping)
MMM.
I SAID...
THE DUMPLINGS ARE MY FAVORITE
PART--JUST SUPER YUMMY.
THE CHICKEN'S REALLY FRESH.
LOTS OF FLAVOR,
WHICH IS A TRADEMARK
OF EVERYTHING THEY PUT OUT HERE.
(Kirstie) CHICKEN
AND BLACK BEAN BURRITO.
THIS IS THE KIND OF PLACE
I LIKE TO WORK.
I GET A LOT MORE
CREATIVITY.
YOU GOT CAJUN MEAT LOAF.
THE BURRITO DEL SUR.
(Guy) SWEET POTATOES
ARE GOING IN THE BURRITO?
SOUTHERN GOES MEXICO.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM.
A WONDERFUL BLEND
OF FLAVORS.
(Kirstie) POT ROAST.
I CAN SEE MAMA
IN THE KITCHEN COOKING.
THAT'S HOW GOOD IT IS?
YEAH.
HANDMADE FROM SCRATCH,
LIKE THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC...
PATTIES UP.
SALMON PATTIES.
ABSOLUTELY PHENOMENAL.
BUT THESE DON'T START IN A CAN.
EACH TIME YOU GUYS GET A FISH
IN, YOU BREAK IT DOWN?
I DO.
I LIKE THAT ATTITUDE.
DEFINITELY.
SLICE IT IN ABOUT
8-OUNCE PIECES,
DICE IT IN LITTLE CUBES,
SOAK THOSE IN WATER.
GET ALL OF OUR
INGREDIENTS TOGETHER--
PARSLEY,
PULVERIZED ONIONS.
PULVERIZED?
YOU WANT THAT JUICE.
YOU WANT IT
TO BREAK DOWN
BECAUSE YOU'RE NOT
PRECOOKING THE ONION,
SO YOU DON'T WANT A BIG CHUNK
OF ONION IN THERE.
EXACTLY.
FIVE WHISKED EGGS.
GOTTA HAVE A BINDER--
MUSTARD.
(whistles) THAT'S A LOT
OF WHOLE GRAIN.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED, THOUGH.
IT'S NOT THAT SHARP.
MAYO, CELERY,
SQUEEZED LEMON JUICE,
LEMON ZEST, DILL WEED.
THAT'S A LOT OF DILL.
BUT DILL AND SALMON
GO HAND IN HAND.
THEY DO.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
OKAY.
SO MIX IT ALL UP,
WITH THE DILL,
THE WHOLE GRAIN.
IT SEEMED LIKE A LOT,
BUT WHEN YOU MIX IT UP,
IT'S EVENLY DISPERSED.
IT IS.
THIS IS JUST REGULAR
WHITE BREAD--
BREADCRUMB WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER ON IT.
AND WE LIKE TO LET THIS SIT
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
LET SOME OF THOSE BREADCRUMBS
ABSORB SOME OF THE MOISTURE,
KIND OF TIGHTEN
THIS WHOLE THING UP.
THEN WE'LL FORM
THE PATTY.
ROLL IT IN SOME
JAPANESE BREADCRUMBS.
OH, SOME PANKO.
NOW OVER TO THE FLATTOP.
OH, AND THEY GO
PRETTY THICK.
OH, YEAH.
AND NOW I PUSH 'EM DOWN.
A LITTLE SQUISH.
FOUR MINUTES EACH SIDE?
FOUR MINUTES EACH SIDE.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
HONEY-ORANGE BUTTER,
WHICH COMES
WITH THE SALMON PATTIES.
PRE-SOFTENED BUTTER.
AND THEN GOES THE...
HONEY.
AND WE'LL ADD
A HALF AN ORANGE.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, IT LOOKS
LIKE THEY'RE DONE.
THAT'S A LOT
OF SALMON PATTY.
IT IS.
THE BUTTER FOR YOU.
OKAY.
MMM. THAT'S NICE.
DILL RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
SALMON COMES IN.
HERE'S WHAT
I DIG ABOUT IT.
THERE'S A LOT OF CRUNCH
ON THAT CAKE.
WITHOUT HAVING
THE DEEP-FRIED, AS WELL...
WITHOUT DEEP-FRYING IT.
WHICH IS REALLY NICE.
THE NICE LITTLE TOUCH
OF ADDING THE BUTTER...
BRINGS IT ALL TOGETHER.
WONDERFUL.
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
(woman) SALMON PATTIES.
IT'S FRESH. IT'S SIMPLE.
IT'S SPICED JUST RIGHT.
THE HONEY-ORANGE BUTTER--
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT POP.
THEY'RE EXCELLENT, GOOD
AS EVERYTHING ELSE ON THE MENU.
BARBECUE SLIDER.
FANTASTIC, WHOLESOME,
GOOD FOOD.
THAT WAS ON POINT.
YOU COME IN,
AND IT'S JUST LIKE HOME.
YOU DON'T FEEL LIKE
YOU HAVE TO DRESS UP.
YOU HAVE TO WEAR CLOTHES?
YOU CAN'T COME IN,
LIKE, YOUR PAJAMAS?
I'D JUST LIKE TO SEE YOU GUYS
HERE IN A COUPLE SNUGGIES.
(laughter)
NEXT STOP...
THE FOOD'S FANTASTIC.
WE'RE HEADING TO PROVIDENCE...
SHORT STACK STARTED.
WHERE COMFORT FOOD...
YOUR JOHNNYCAKES.
RHODE ISLAND STYLE.
ARE THESE AS GOOD
AS NANA'S?
YEP, MAYBE BETTER.
(whispering)
DON'T SAY THAT.
YOU KNOW, WHENEVER
THE FAMILY AND I ARE HERE
IN PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND,
TO VISIT THE IN-LAWS,
I'M ALWAYS KEEPING MY EYE OUT
FOR THE LATEST AND GREATEST
IN TRIPLE "D" JOINTS.
NOW HERE WE ARE
IN SOUTH PROVIDENCE
AT A DINER
THAT WAS BUILT IN 1947,
AND I HEAR THEY'RE KNOCKING OUT
THE RHODE ISLAND FAVORITES,
LIKE CHOWDER
AND JOHNNYCAKES.
WE'RE HERE, KIDS,
LIBERTY ELM DINER.
SWEET.
(woman) JOHNNYCAKES.
CHOWDER WILL BE RIGHT UP.
THEY HAVE JOHNNYCAKES.
AND THEY'RE A CROSS
BETWEEN PANCAKES AND GRITS.
IT'S A RHODE ISLAND THING.
(woman)
BOWL OF CHOWDER, JUDY.
(Guy) MY WIFE
IS FROM RHODE ISLAND,
AND WHEN YOU GROW UP
IN RHODE ISLAND,
YOU HAVE A LOT OF CHOWDER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE CHOWDER?
THE CHOWDER IS FABULOUS.
THE FOOD IS GREAT, AND IT'S GOT
THE CLASSIC FEEL OF A DINER.
THANKS TO CAROL DEFECIANI...
OKAY, WE GOT
TWO EGGS SCRAMBLED.
WHO HAD A PROBLEM.
I WANTED TO HAVE BREAKFAST
SOMEWHERE IN MY NEIGHBORHOOD.
SHORT STACK STARTED.
AND THERE WAS NOPLACE.
TILL CAROL FOUND THIS PLACE.
I KEPT DRIVING BY A DINER
THAT WAS CLOSED.
SO SHE FIXED IT UP
AND STARTED SERVING UP...
TABLE ONE IS UP.
RHODE ISLAND CLASSICS.
WHO'S GOT
THE JOHNNYCAKES?
JOHNNYCAKES--
VERY GOOD.
JOHNNYCAKES COME FROM
RHODE ISLAND, YOU SAY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN PROVE IT?
"JOY OF COOKING."
HELD TOGETHER
WITH DUCT TAPE.
"RHODE ISLAND, THE CENTER OF
THE MODERN JOHNNYCAKE UNIVERSE.
"JOHNNYCAKES ARE USUALLY
EATEN AT BREAKFAST.
"USE ONLY
STONE-GROUND CORNMEAL,
AND SERVE THE CAKES
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE."
WELL, THAT'S
WHAT WE'VE GOT,
STONE-GROUND CORNMEAL
RIGHT HERE FROM RHODE ISLAND.
GONNA ADD THE SUGAR...
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
GIVE IT A QUICK STIR.
SOME BOILING WATER.
RIGHT.
AND IT'S GONNA THICKEN
JUST FROM THE HOT WATER.
LIKE GRITS.
YEP, IT DOES
LOOK LIKE GRITS.
SO NOW WE'VE GOT
A THICK CORNMEAL BATTER,
AND IT'S READY
TO GO ON THE FLATTOP.
THROW
A LITTLE BUTTER DOWN.
RIGHT.
WE GOT OUR BATTER
READY TO GO.
HOW MANY
COME WITH AN ORDER?
THREE.
THEY'RE VERY FILLING.
SO YOU PUT A LITTLE
CRUST ON BOTH SIDES?
YEP.
FLIP IT.
LET EACH SIDE COOK
FOR SIX MINUTES.
AND IT'S READY TO GO.
NOW WHAT DO YOU LIKE
TO EAT YOURS WITH?
I LIKE SYRUP ON MINE.
REALLY?
YEP.
I LIKE BACON FAT.
I'VE HEARD OF THAT, TOO,
BUT I'M GIVING IT TO YOU
WITH PURE MAPLE SYRUP
AND BUTTER.
WITH MAPLE SYRUP
IT LOOKS LIKE
A POLENTA CAKE.
IT DOES.
WHAT I HAVE TO DO
IS ASK LORI
WHY SHE NEVER TOLD ME
ABOUT THESE,
BECAUSE I'M GONNA BE
JOHNNYCAKE-ING IT EVERY DAY.
I'M A HUGE CORNMEAL FAN.
IT'S CREAMY. IT'S GOT TEXTURE.
A LITTLE CHEWIER
THAN A PANCAKE.
I WAS GONNA SAY, I ENJOY IT
MORE THAN A PANCAKE.
HERE ARE YOUR JOHNNYCAKES.
IT HAS A LITTLE FRIED FLAVOR
TO IT--VERY GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF JOHNNYCAKES?
ARE THESE AS GOOD
AS NANA'S?
YEP, MAYBE BETTER.
(whispering)
DON'T SAY THAT.
(normal voice)
SO WHAT GOES WITH THIS?
I'M GONNA SERVE IT WITH
THE STATE DRINK OF RHODE ISLAND,
COFFEE MILK.
IT'S COFFEE SYRUP.
ICE-COLD MILK.
THIS IS BEFORE
THEY HAD FRAPPUCCINOS?
OH, YEAH, WAY BEFORE.
IT TASTES LIKE
AN ICED LATTE.
DEEP, RICH COFFEE FLAVOR,
CREAMINESS OF THE MILK,
THAT ALONG WITH
JOHNNYCAKES.
IF YOU MAKE THIS
FOR A RHODE ISLANDER,
THIS IS THE STAPLE?
THEY WILL LIKE IT.
I GOTTA GO SEE
IF MY WIFE LIKES THIS.
THAT IS MY FAVORITE. IT'S PRETTY
MUCH WHAT I WAS RAISED ON.
BEFORE I EVEN HAD COFFEE,
I HAD COFFEE MILK.
LIKE A MELTED-DOWN
COFFEE MILK SHAKE.
YOU CAN MAKE IT AS SWEET
OR AS MILKY AS YOU LIKE IT.
THE FOOD'S FANTASTIC.
THEIR WHOLE MENU IS REALLY
UNIQUE AND REALLY GREAT.
(woman) THERE'S
YOUR LIBERTY BURGER.
ROASTED VEGETABLE
QUESADILLAS--GREAT.
(Carol) BLACK AND BLUE.
GAZPACHO SOUP?
THIS DOESN'T REALLY SEEM
EXACTLY LIKE DINER FOOD.
THIS IS WHAT
YOU COME HERE FOR.
THEY GOT A VEGAN MENU
AND EVERYTHING.
(man) IT'S A GREAT MENU.
MOST OF IT'S LOCAL PRODUCE,
LOCAL GOODS.
WE'RE TRYING TO SUPPORT
LOCAL FARMERS.
THIS IS ONE OF THE FIRST DINERS
I THINK THAT WE'VE SEEN,
FARM TO TABLE.
(Carol) HERE'S
A GREEK SALAD, "G."
AND THIS ONE...
(Carol) CHOWDER.
THAT'S COAST TO THE TABLE.
WE'RE ONLY A FEW MILES
FROM THE WATERS
THE CLAMS WERE PULLED OUT OF.
MONSTER QUAHOGS. WHAT, IS THERE
A CHEESEBURGER INSIDE OF THAT?
NO, NO, NO.
THESE ARE GONNA
GO FOR CHOWDER.
YEP.
WE'RE GONNA OPEN THESE UP.
WE'RE GONNA SHUCK 'EM.
SHUCKS.
LOOK AT YOU. I GAVE YOU
THE TOUGHEST ONE IN THE BATCH.
THERE WE GO.
YOU GOT IT.
IT GAVE ME A BIT
OF A FIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA THROW 'EM
IN THE BOILING WATER.
AND THERE THEY ARE.
WE'LL LET THESE COOK
A LITTLE BIT, NOT VERY LONG.
OKAY, SO WHILE THAT'S GOING,
NOW WE'RE GONNA SAUTé?
WE'RE GONNA USE A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL, EXTRA VIRGIN.
AND WE'RE GONNA
THROW IN SOME ONIONS
AND GET THOSE
A LITTLE BROWNED.
NOW WE'RE GONNA STRAIN
OUR BROTH INTO HERE.
WIRE SIEVE,
AS WELL AS CHEESECLOTH,
BECAUSE WE'RE GONNA HAVE LITTLE
BITS OF SAND AND SO FORTH,
AND WE DON'T WANT
ANYTHING GOING THROUGH.
JUST IN CASE
WE FIND A PEARL.
NOW WE'VE GOT
SOME BROTH HAPPENING.
MMM, IT SMELLS GREAT.
SMELLS LIKE THE OCEAN. ADD SOME
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
A FEW BAY LEAVES,
FRESH THYME.
GONNA JUST LET THAT
COOK A LITTLE BIT.
NEXT WE'LL ADD
THE POTATOES.
LET THESE COOK
UNTIL THE POTATOES GET SOFT.
GET FORK TENDER?
YEP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR CLAMS
THAT WE'VE COOKED AND STRAINED,
DICE THEM
AND ADD THEM TO THE MIX.
OKAY.
AND HERE WE GO.
GONNA ADD THE CREAM.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT COOK
FOR A WHILE, AND IT'LL THICKEN.
PULL SOME OF THE STARCH OUT
OF THE POTATOES--TIGHTEN IT UP.
YEP.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET THIS COOK DOWN FOR?
OH, WE'LL PROBABLY LET THIS COOK
DOWN ABOUT A HALF AN HOUR.
LET ME SERVE YOU A BOWL.
WELL, I DON'T THINK YOU'RE GONNA
PART WITH THE WHOLE POT OF IT,
SO YEAH,
A BOWL WOULD BE FINE.
THAT'S GREAT.
BIG RICH, DEEP FLAVOR.
PICK UP SOME OF THE
HERBACEOUS-NESS OF THE THYME.
POTATOES ARE NICE AND TENDER.
CLAMS AREN'T OVERCOOKED.
WHEN YOU HAVE THAT MUCH
CLAM GOING INTO IT--
THOSE BIG QUAHOGS--
THE FLAVOR'S REAL.
TAKE A QUART TO GO?
I'D TAKE
MORE THAN A QUART.
ACTUALLY, I'LL TAKE THIS.
(laughing)
(Carol) BOWL OF CHOWDER.
THE CHOWDER IS AWESOME.
NICE CHUNKY POTATOES.
FILLED WITH CLAMS.
NOT TOO THICK
BUT NOT THIN EITHER.
IT'S ALWAYS TOUGH IN CALIFORNIA
TO MAKE LORI HAPPY WITH CHOWDER.
THIS IS THE WAY
YOU REMEMBER IT?
IT ABSOLUTELY IS.
IT'S A NICE MIXTURE
OF SOME LOCAL SPECIALS,
BUT TRADITIONAL THINGS
YOU MIGHT EXPECT AT A DINER.
LIKE A TURKEY SANDWICH...
IT'S FRESH, TASTY.
FRESH FROM THE OVEN...
LOOK AT THAT. I LOVE
THE HERBS UNDERNEATH THERE.
IT'S GREAT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
AT THE LIBERTY ELM DINER
IN PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND...
(Carol) BOWL OF CHOWDER.
THE MARY POPPINS
OF CHOWDER OVER HERE.
CAROL DEFECIANI IS DOING
NEW ENGLAND FAVORITES...
WHO'S GOT
THE JOHNNYCAKES?
AND THE REST
OF THE CLASSIC DINER MENU...
(Carol) HERE'S
YOUR OMELET, JUDY.
EVEN FRESH ROASTED TURKEY...
GOT A COUPLE
TURKEY SANDWICHES.
FOR THE TURKEY SANDWICH.
OH, MY GOSH.
NICE FRESH BEEFSTEAK TOMATO
RIGHT OUT OF SOMEBODY'S GARDEN.
AND PEA GREENS,
WHICH YOU DON'T SEE A LOT.
WE'RE GONNA
ROAST THE TURKEY,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A NICE SANDWICH OUT OF IT.
I LIKE IT.
TAKE A LITTLE BUTTER.
YOU WANT TO GET INTO IT?
NO. I HAVE
A SUSPENDED LICENSE.
DRIVING
WHILE BUTTERING TURKEYS
DOESN'T GO OVER WELL
IN CALIFORNIA?
EXPLAIN THAT.
I'M GONNA TRY TO GET SOME
UNDER THE SKIN.
WITHOUT PULLING IT
AND TEARING THE SKIN.
YEP. ADD A LITTLE PEPPER.
OKAY.
A LITTLE SALT.
I'M GONNA RUB THAT AROUND,
CRISP UP THE SKIN
A LITTLE BIT.
DIG IT.
SOME FRESH THYME.
I'M NOT EVEN GONNA CHOP IT.
THAT'S THE WAY
TO GO WITH IT.
GREAT FLAVOR
IN THE STEMS.
ADD SOME FRESH CILANTRO.
SO THAT'S ON TOP SO IT'LL
COOK DOWN INTO IT.
IN THE PAN?
YEP.
POP IT IN THE OVEN AT--
325 FOR 2 1/2 HOURS.
HERE'S OUR TURKEY.
OH. I LOVE THE HERBS
UNDERNEATH THERE.
WE'VE LET THIS COOL.
LETTING IT COOL
REALLY IS THE KEY.
FEEL LIKE CARVING?
THE THEORY IS
YOU COME IN
AND YOU TAKE THE BREAST
ALL THE WAY OFF OF THE BONE.
IT'LL PEEL RIGHT OFF
BY HAND.
THEN YOU GET A SUPERCLEAN
REMOVAL OF IT.
YOU JUST COME RIGHT IN HERE
ON TOP OF THE BREASTBONE,
AND THEN PULL BACK
A LITTLE BIT.
SO NOW YOU SEE HOW IT ALL
CAME OFF REAL NICE AND CLEAN?
OH, BEAUTIFUL.
SO WHEN YOU WANT
TO GO AHEAD AND SLICE IT,
YOU GET NICE CONSISTENT,
UNIFORM SLICES.
VERY NICE.
AND LOOK AT THOSE HERBS.
BUILD ME THAT SANDWICH.
THIS VERY NICE
TOASTED BREAD.
OH, GOOD,
NOT A FLIP-FLOP.
GOTTA MAYONNAISE
BOTH SIDES.
MY WIFE LOVES MAYONNAISE.
HEY, LORI, YOU GOTTA SEE
HOW MUCH MAYONNAISE
SHE'S PUTTING
ON THIS THING.
IT'S A RHODE ISLAND THING.
I FIGURED IT OUT.
BIG LOCAL TOMATOES,
SOME NICE SLICES OF TURKEY.
GET SOME HERBS IN THERE.
SOME LOVELY LOCALLY GROWN
FRESH PEA GREENS.
PEA GREENS,
AS IN GREEN PEAS?
YEP.
SO THE LITTLE LEAVES
FROM THAT?
MM-HMM.
THIS WILL BE THE FIRST TIME
I'VE EVER HAD PEA GREENS
ON A SANDWICH.
PUT ANY MORE IN THERE,
I'LL TURN INTO A COW.
NO, YOU WON'T.
AND WE'RE READY
TO SLICE IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THE TURKEY'S
GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
THE BREAD IS THE PERFECT CHOICE,
CUT THE RIGHT THICKNESS.
THERE'S MOISTURE IN THE TOMATO,
KIND OF MELTED INTO THE BREAD.
AND YOUR TURKEY--
YOU COOKED THIS ONE RIGHT.
AND THE PEA GREENS--THE PEA
GREENS MAKE THAT SANDWICH.
THOSE ARE GREAT.
IF YOU LIKE TURKEY SANDWICHES,
THAT IS AS GOOD
AS YOU'LL GET 'EM.
MMM.
HERE YOU GUYS GO.
TURKEY SANDWICH.
IT REMINDS ME OF TURKEY
DINNER ON THANKSGIVING.
PEA GREEN'S GOT A NICE
CRUNCHY TASTE.
I LIKE IT BETTER THAN LETTUCE.
HUNTER, YOU'RE HAVING
THE TURKEY? WHAT DO YOU THINK?
REALLY GOOD.
IT'S FRESH, TASTY.
THEY DO A REALLY GOOD JOB.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
(Carol) A CUP OF CHOWDER.
WOW, IT'S AMAZING.
EVERYTHING YOU WANT.
HERE'S YOUR MIGA.
I THINK WHEN YOU CAN FIND
THAT KIND OF RESTAURANT
IN ANY COMMUNITY,
YOU'RE LUCKY.
BUT TO FIND IT
IN A SMALL, LITTLE DINER
ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF PROVIDENCE--
PRETTY COOL.
WORKING PEOPLE DESERVE
TO EAT GOOD FOOD, TOO.
AS WELL. I AGREE.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
BUT DON'T WORRY, THERE'S PLENTY
MORE PLACES TO FIND
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO WORCESTER--SHISER--
SHISER--SHISER?
EXACTLY.
YEAH, SO WORCESTER--
SHISER--SHISER SAUCE.
(laughing)