HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
GO. GO. GO.
WHOO-HOO!
FARM...
YOU BUY LOCAL,
SERVE LOCALS.
HERE YOU GO, TIM.
TO TABLE...
(man) YOU CAN PLAY PING-PONG
WHEN YOU'RE WAITING FOR
YOUR PIZZA.
IN KENTUCKY...
(woman) BURGERS
ARE READY TO PICK UP.
THE FORMER TRAIN STATION...
IT'S A LITTLE SLICE
OF HEAVEN.
HERE'S THE HOT BROWN.
WHERE THEY'RE SCRATCH-MAKING
IT ALL...
THAT IS MASSIVE. THAT IS
DOWN-HOME GOODNESS RIGHT THERE.
ON
ST. SIMONS ISLAND, GEORGIA...
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
AN ISLAND FAVORITE...
FOR ANY KIND OF FOOD
YOU WANT.
CRANKING OUT
ISLAND FAVORITES...
HERE'S YOUR FRITTERS.
MMM.
AND IN WASHINGTON, D.C...
I LIKE IT.
THE PIZZERIA...
(man) COMING AROUND.
WHERE SERVING IT UP...
REALLY FRESH, LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
MEANS PING-PONG AND PIZZA.
MMM.
PHENOMENAL. THAT GOOD.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D," WE LOVE
HITTING THE BIG-NAME PLACES,
BUT NOT USUALLY FOR
WHAT THEY'RE KNOWN FOR.
LIKE WE WENT TO VEGAS.
IT WASN'T FOR THE GAMBLING.
IT WAS FOR THE STROMBOLI
AT FOUR KEGS.
AND WE HIT MIAMI.
IT WASN'T FOR THE BEACHES.
NO, IT WAS FOR THE OFF-THE-HOOK
MOFONGO AT BENNY'S SEAFOOD.
SO HERE WE ARE IN THE HEART
OF THOROUGHBRED COUNTRY,
MIDWAY, KENTUCKY,
NOT TO SEE THE DERBY WINNERS.
NOPE, TO SEE WHAT'S COOKING
AT WALLACE STATION.
(woman) BURGERS
ARE READY TO PICK UP.
IT'S A LITTLE SLICE
OF HEAVEN.
THEY'RE LOOKING GOOD.
THEY REALLY WENT
OUT OF THEIR WAY
BUILDING THESE BURGERS
AND SANDWICHES.
ALL RIGHT, WE HAVE
THE HAM AND BRIE SANDWICH.
EVERYTHING'S MADE FROM SCRATCH.
'CAUSE OWNER OUITA MICHEL
INSISTS ON IT.
I'M GONNA NEED SOME GRITS
PROBABLY NEXT WEEK.
YOU HAVE ONE
OF THE OLDEST BUILDINGS,
WHICH WAS THE TRAIN STATION,
AND YOU PUT A FUNKY LITTLE
SANDWICH/BURGER JOINT
INSIDE OF IT.
YEAH.
EVERYBODY NEEDS A JOINT.
MMM.
YOU BUY LOCAL,
SERVE LOCALS.
YEAH.
THERE YOU GO, TIM.
OUITA IS A SPECIALIST
IN KENTUCKY CUISINE.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE EATING
A PART OF THE BLUEGRASS STATE
WHEN YOU COME HERE.
LIKE THEIR TAKE
ON A KENTUCKY CLASSIC
CALLED A HOT BROWN.
USUALLY AN OPEN-FACED TURKEY,
HAM AND CHEESE SAUCE SANDWICH,
THEY'RE DOING IT AS A PANINI
OR AS A BURGER...
BIG BROWN BURGER.
CRANKED OUT...
TWO BURGERS.
BY KENTUCKY-BORN CHEF
SAM BROWN.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO?
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE BIG BROWN BURGER.
THIS IS LOCAL BEEF.
WE DO JUST OVER 6 OUNCES.
OKAY, SO WE MAKE THESE UP. ARE
THEY GONNA GET ANY SEASONING?
THEY GET
A LITTLE CHICKEN SALT.
THEIR SIGNATURE SEASONING.
THEY INVENTED IT FOR CHICKEN,
AND NOW IT'S GOING ON
THE BURGERS, TOO.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE ONTO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME CHICKEN SALT.
START WITH 3 CUPS OF KOSHER,
BLACK PEPPER,
SOME PAPRIKA...
FOR A LITTLE COLOR THERE.
SOME CAYENNE.
PUT THE TOP ON,
AND GIVE HER A SHAKE.
WORKING OUT IN THE KITCHEN
WITH GUY.
(exhales) I'M GONNA NEED
A DOUGHNUT.
SHE'S READY.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MORNAY.
MORNAY IS A CHEESE SAUCE,
A WHITE CHEESE SAUCE.
YEAH.
(whistles)
HEY, BETSY ROSS CALLED.
SHE WANTS HER POT BACK.
OH, YEAH.
WOW.
BUTTER.
WE'RE READY TO ADD THE FLOUR.
MAKE A ROUX. MILK HERE.
YOU HAVE TO TEMPER THIS IN
A LITTLE BIT RIGHT HERE
AT THE VERY BEGINNING.
POUR IT IN TOO FAST, YOU MAKE
YOURSELF SOME DUMPLINGS.
YOU READY FOR IT ALL?
BRING IT ON.
WAIT UNTIL IT GETS THICK.
TALK ABOUT TIGHT.
NOW IT'S CREAMY DREAMY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
KOSHER SALT AND SOME CAYENNE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR CHEESE.
IT'S A VERMONT CHEDDAR.
IT'S A SLOW-CONTROLLED MELT
THAT'LL KEEP IT FROM CLUMPING.
LOOK AT THAT STUFF RIGHT THERE,
NICE AND CREAMY.
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
CHICKEN SALT ONE SIDE,
PUT A THUMBPRINT IN THE TOP.
I'M GONNA CHICKEN SALT
THE OTHER
AND THEN PUT A LITTLE
WORCESTERSHIRE OVER THE TOP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA CAP IT.
YOU WANT MEDIUM, MEDIUM-RARE?
MEDIUM-RARE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND FLIP. ALL RIGHT.
OH, THAT'S CALLED GRIDDLE CRUNCH
RIGHT THERE.
BUNS DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA HEAT SOME HAM,
BACON.
DOUSE IT WITH SOME MORNAY.
OKAY, READY TO GO?
YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT. NICE.
ALL RIGHT, THE HAM
AND THE BACON, TOMATO.
AND THAT IS BIG BROWN BURGER.
JUST TAKE A LOOKY-LOO
AT THAT.
IT JUST SOUNDS GOOD.
(speaking indistinctly)
(laughs)
MMM.
THIS, TO ME,
RIVALS WITH THE TRADITIONAL
ASPECTS OF THE HOT BROWN.
I THINK I MIGHT
LIKE THIS BETTER.
NICE BEEF. GREAT BUN.
NOT TOO MUCH MORNAY.
YOU'RE NOT LOSING
THE OTHER FLAVORS.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
I'M GONNA TAKE ONE MORE BITE.
I DON'T WANT TO DO THIS,
BUT I'M DOING THIS FOR YOU.
MMM. I WILL BE BACK,
AND I WILL ORDER THAT.
AWESOME.
BIG BROWN BURGER.
BACON ON A BURGER,
YOU CAN'T MISS.
AND THEN IT'S GOT
THAT CHEESE SAUCE ON IT.
IT WAS AWESOME.
(man) IT'S ONE OF
OUR MOST FAMOUS DISHES.
PUTTING IT HERE ON A BURGER
IS JUST FANTASTIC.
CUBANO UP.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WITH
ANYTHING THAT YOU ORDER HERE.
A LITTLE CHICKEN SAUCE.
FROM FRESH FRIED CHICKEN...
CRISPY.
IT TASTES WONDERFUL.
TO SOUP AND CORNBREAD...
FRESH, JUST LIKE
EVERYTHING ELSE.
AND THREE KINDS
OF SANDWICH BREAD.
WE MAKE A LIGHT RYE, A COUNTRY
WHITE AND A WHOLE WHEAT.
THE BREAD REALLY
MAKES THE SANDWICH.
BREAD MAKES
THE SANDWICH.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME COUNTRY WHITE BREAD.
I'M GONNA THROW IN
SOME WARM WATER.
DRY-ACTIVE YEAST
AND THEN FEED IT
WITH A LITTLE SUGAR.
NOW GIVE HER
A LITTLE MIXY-MIX.
MIXY.
OKAY, SO THE YEAST IN THAT
HAS ACTIVATED.
HOW MANY GALLONS OF FLOUR?
3 GALLONS.
3 GALLONS OF HIGH GLUTEN.
YOU WANT THAT ELASTICITY
WITH THE GLUTEN.
SOME SALT.
HIT THE GREEN BUTTON
FOR ME.
SO THIS TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES
TO COME TOGETHER.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE'RE GONNA PULL IT OUT,
GET IT INTO A BOWL.
COVER IT WITH SOME PLASTIC.
WE LET IT PROOF.
WE'VE LET OUR DOUGH RISE.
IT'S DOUBLED.
SO SMACK IT DOWN.
SMACK IT.
I'M JUST GONNA LIGHTLY DUST
THE AREA. WHOO.
SO WE'RE GONNA CUT THIS,
WEIGH IT.
3 1/2 POUNDS
IS WHAT YOU'RE GOING FOR.
3 1/2 POUNDS.
THAT MIGHT BE CLOSE
TO ON.
I THINK IT MIGHT BE.
OKAY, LET'S SEE HERE.
JUST OVER BY A 1/2 POUND.
JUST OVER, NOT SO BAD.
WELL...
YOUR TURN.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
OH, NO. NO, YOU'RE BENDING
YOUR FINGER ON IT.
I WAS JUST KEEPING IT BALANCED
OVER HERE.
I KNOW THE TRUTH.
WE'RE GONNA BUST 'EM OUT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA KNEAD A LITTLE.
WE JUST WANT TO MAKE IT
LONG ENOUGH FOR THE LOAF PAN.
YOU WANT ME TO SPRAY THAT?
NOW WE'LL PUT THE LOAVES
IN THE PAN.
THOSE WILL PROOF UP.
THAT'S GONNA TAKE ABOUT--
PROBABLY ABOUT 30.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
ARE WE GONNA BAKE IT AT?
350.
IN FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
THEN WHEN WE PULL IT OUT
OF THE OVEN, WE'LL LET IT REST.
EXACTLY.
ALL RIGHT.
WHOA.
THAT IS MASSIVE.
LOOK AT THAT.
CAN I TRY A PIECE?
OF COURSE.
THAT IS DOWN-HOME GOODNESS
RIGHT THERE.
SO NOW THAT WE GOT THIS DONE,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE WITH IT?
PRETTY SNAZZY SELECTION
YOU GOT HERE.
COUNTRY HAM AND PIMIENTO.
DO YOU GUYS MAKE
YOUR OWN PIMIENTO?
PIMIENTO CHEESE, OF COURSE.
SHREDDED WHITE CHEDDAR,
CREAM CHEESE,
MAYONNAISE, PIMIENTOS,
HOT SAUCE,
WORCESTERSHIRE,
PURéED ONION.
OH.
PIMIENTO CHEESE, TOMATO,
COUNTRY HAM,
AND THEN IT'S GRILLED
ON THE PANINI PRESS.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU PANINI-ED THAT NICE.
I'M JUST SALIVATING FIRST,
JUST WARMING UP THE JETS.
(laughs)
MMM.
REALLY GOOD.
IT'S GOT REALLY GOOD CHEW.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU SOMETHING,
YOU DON'T BUY PIMIENTO CHEESE
IF PEOPLE MAKE IT THEMSELVES.
THAT RIGHT THERE
HAS ALL THE FLAVORS,
AND TO KNOW THAT
WE JUST MADE THE BREAD...
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
YOU DON'T FIND THE FRESH
HOMEMADE STUFF VERY OFTEN.
FRESH AND DELICIOUS.
DELICIOUS?
ABSOLUTELY.
LEG AND THIGH LUNCH UP.
THE FOOD IS ALL HOME-COOKED.
HERE'S THE HOT BROWN.
IT'S THE PINNACLE OF
KENTUCKY CUISINE RIGHT HERE.
BIG BROWN BURGER.
THIS GIRL SHOULD HAVE
A LICENSE TO DO THAT.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADING TO GEORGIA...
TABLE 12.
ALL THE FOOD IS VERY, VERY GOOD.
TO GRAB SOME GROUPER.
QUITE THE GROUPER.
I CAN SEE WHY
THAT'S A HIT.
SO I'M HERE IN GEORGIA
ON THE HISTORIC ISLAND
OF ST. SIMONS.
IT'S 14 MILES LONG, 4 MILES WIDE
AND HAS A POPULATION
OF 14,000 PEOPLE.
NOW BEING SO CLOSE TO THE WATER,
OH, IT'S GOT ME
THINKING ABOUT SEAFOOD.
SO THE FOLKS FROM THE LOCAL
TROLLEY COMPANY TOLD ME
WHEN THE TOURISTS ASK
WHERE DO THE LOCALS GO,
THEY SEND 'EM HERE
TO BLACKWATER GRILL.
TABLE 23.
BEST RESTAURANT
ON THE ISLAND.
SHRIMP.
I'VE NEVER EATEN ANYWHERE
AS GOOD AS THIS PLACE.
REALLY?
GLORIA, PICKUP.
EVERYBODY
TREATS YOU LIKE FAMILY.
HOW IN THE WORLD ARE YA?
'CAUSE OWNER JOHN HOWTON...
GOOD EVENING.
LIVES TO GIVE FOLKS
WHAT THEY WANT.
WE'RE GONNA DO ALL THE COOKING,
AND WE'LL DO THE DISHES, TOO.
WELL, CHEF JAMIE CADDEN
WILL DO THE COOKING...
TABLE 12.
ALL THE SOUTHERN FAVORITES...
PICKUP.
AND COASTAL CLASSICS.
ALWAYS FRESH, ALWAYS GOOD.
BRUNSWICK STEW.
WE USE
THE FRESHEST INGREDIENTS.
CHECK THIS OUT--FRESH SHRIMP
FROM THE COAST, NOT FROZEN.
FRESH SHRIMP.
LIKE IT.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
STRAIGHT OUT OF THE SOUND.
IT'S ALL FRESH,
AND IT'S ALL LOCAL.
LIKE THE GROUPER...
QUITE THE GROUPER.
AND THIS BLACKWATER ORIGINAL.
WE'RE MAKING
THE GROUPER DAUFUSKIE.
DAUFUSKIE.
THAT'S AN ISLAND OFF THE COAST
OF SOUTH CAROLINA.
OKAY, SO HOW DO YOU KNOW
IF IT'S SUPER-DUPER GROUPER?
WELL, I GET MY FISH FRESH
JUST ABOUT EVERY DAY.
FILLET IT OUT.
6-OUNCE PORTIONS.
AND THEN DREDGE IT.
YEP. ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
KOSHER SALT,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION.
THAT GETS ALL MIXED UP, AND THEN
WE BRING THE GROUPER IN.
COAT IT UP.
AND GROUPER IS A PRETTY POPULAR
FISH IN THIS AREA?
YEAH, IT'S NOT TOO FISHY
OR OILY, YOU KNOW.
THIS MEANS TOO FISHY...
TOO FISHY.
AND THIS MEANS TOO OILY.
YEAH, YOU KNOW.
I ALWAYS WONDERED WHAT
THOSE HAWAIIAN DANCES WERE.
TOO FISHY. TOO OILY.
OKAY.
(laughs)
DREDGE IT A LITTLE MORE.
SHAKE IT OFF A LITTLE BIT.
AND WE'RE READY.
TWO PANS READY TO ROCK?
YES, SIR.
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA CARAMELIZE SOME
ONIONS AND SAUTé SOME MUSHROOMS.
OKAY.
SOME JULIENNE WHITE ONIONS
AND SLICED BUTTON MUSHROOMS,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
AND IT'LL START BROWNING
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU WANT TO GLAZE IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WHITE WINE
AND JUST LET THEM COOK DOWN.
NOW WE GET THE GROUPER
IN THE LITTLE PAN.
YEP. CLARIFIED BUTTER,
GET THAT NICE AND HOT.
HE WANTS THIS SUPER HOT,
SO HE LAYS IT DOWN.
IT'S GONNA MAKE
A NICE LITTLE CRUST.
GROUPER FILLET
STRAIGHT INTO THE PAN.
HEAR THE SIZZLE?
(sizzling)
BOTH SIDES.
THEN WE FINISH IT IN THE OVEN,
PROBABLY THREE MINUTES.
THE ONIONS ARE CARAMELIZED.
THE MUSHROOMS ARE DONE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE DAUFUSKIE SAUCE.
DAUFUSKIE SAUCE.
SOME MAYONNAISE...
FOOD LUBE,
AS I LIKE TO CALL IT.
DRY VERMOUTH...
DOESN'T IT SEEM
A CONTRADICTION OF TERMS?
IT'S WET, BUT--
WHOLE GRAIN DIJON MUSTARD...
OKAY.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
(speaking indistinctly)
WORCESTER.
LEMON JUICE, KOSHER SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC
AND WHITE PEPPER,
TABASCO, GOOD SHOT OF THAT.
(whistles) NICE.
WHISK IT UP.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
YES, SIR.
USE OUR CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND MUSHROOMS ON THE PLATE,
AND OUR FISH IS STRAIGHT OUT
OF THE OVEN.
HIT IT WITH OUR
FAMOUS DAUFUSKIE SAUCE,
A LITTLE PARSLEY GARNISH.
AND THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE LOVE
HERE AT BLACKWATER GRILL.
THIS IS ONE
OF THE BIG HITS?
THIS IS IT.
HM. GREAT CRUNCH
TO THE FISH.
COOKED PERFECTLY.
THE DAUFUSKIE SAUCE--
IT'S GOT SOME ZAP TO IT.
THAT DRY VERMOUTH, KIND OF LIKE
A VODKA, BUT WITH MORE FLAVOR.
YEP, GOT A LITTLE SWEETNESS
AND A TARTNESS FROM THE MUSTARD.
THAT'S EXACTLY IT.
AND THEN YOU GET THESE ONIONS
AND MUSHROOMS
THAT PARLAY INTO IT.
YEP.
MMM. I CAN SEE WHY
THAT'S A HIT.
GROUPER DAUFUSKIE.
COOKED JUST RIGHT,
AND THE SAUCE JUST KIND OF
WAKENS YOUR PALATE UP.
FISH IS FLAKY, GREAT SEASONING
AND TASTE TO IT.
IT ALL JUST COMES TOGETHER
PERFECT. IT'S DELICIOUS.
FIRE TWO GROUPER DAUFUSKIES.
JUST THE PLACE TO GO
FOR ANY KIND OF FOOD YOU WANT.
LIKE THIS LOW COUNTRY STAPLE...
TWO LOW COUNTRY BOILS.
JUST LOVE IT.
YOU'RE A MAN ON A MISSION
RIGHT NOW.
I'M SCARED IF I GET A HAND
TOO CLOSE, I'LL MISS A DIGIT.
BE CAREFUL.
CHECK THIS OUT.
THE CORN, THE POTATOES,
THE SAUSAGE,
AND THEN JUST SEASONED BROTH.
MMM. THIS IS THE WAY TO GO.
YOU CAN GET SO MANY DIFFERENT
THINGS IN ONE RESTAURANT.
'CAUSE THESE GUYS...
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
DID THEIR HOMEWORK.
(John) BEFORE WE EVEN
OPENED THE DOORS...
WELCOME TO
BLACKWATER GRILL.
WE ASKED A BUNCH OF PEOPLE WHAT
THEY LIKE TO SEE DOWN HERE.
CAJUN PASTA.
THAT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
CAJUN FIT RIGHT IN.
FROM JAMBALAYA
TO CRAWFISH éTOUFéE
AND THIS ONE
FROM THE BIG EASY...
BOUDIN FRITTER.
IT'S ACTUALLY VERY NEW ORLEANS.
CAJUN SAUSAGE ROLLED AND FRIED.
HOW DO WE GET STARTED?
I MAKE MY OWN SAUSAGE
HERE IN THE RESTAURANT.
OKAY.
CHOPPED ONION, CELERY,
CHOPPED GREEN ONION,
FRESH GARLIC
AND FRESH CHOPPED PARSLEY.
OKAY.
TURNS INTO A PASTE.
SCRAPE THAT DOWN.
PURéE ONE MORE TIME.
SO SUPER FINE.
YEAH, THAT IS A LOT OF
THE FLAVOR IN YOUR SAUSAGE.
AND THEN WE CAN GO TO THE PORK,
RIGHT INTO THE PAN.
COMBINE IT
WITH SOME SEASONINGS.
KOSHER SALT,
CREOLE SEASONING,
CHILI POWDER,
ROASTED GARLIC POWDER,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
YOU'RE DRAGGING THIS
THROUGH THE KITCHEN.
THIS IS
A HIGHLY SEASONED DISH.
THIS IS GRANULATED ONION,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
AND IT WOULD BE NO CAJUN COOKING
WITHOUT WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
ALWAYS NEED THAT.
ALWAYS. OUR PURéE
FROM THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST...
A LITTLE TABASCO.
IT'S ON EVERY TABLE.
TABASCO.
WE ARE TALKING NEW ORLEANS,
OF COURSE.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
YEAH, I'D SAY
ONE MORE HIT.
SOUNDS GOOD.
THEN MIX IT ALL UP.
THEN WE GET IN THERE
AND MAKE SURE EVERYTHING IS
DISTRIBUTED THROUGHOUT THE MEAT.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE PART.
I LIKE THE TEXTURE OF THIS.
IT'S KIND OF FREAKY,
BUT, YOU KNOW...
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS
AND JUST COOK IT RIGHT UP?
YES, RIGHT TO THE PAN.
SO WHEN YOU FRY IT, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO FRY IT SUPER LONG,
AND YOU KNOW IT'S COOKED
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
RIGHT. RIGHT.
ONCE THIS IS DONE,
WE COOL IT DOWN.
YES, SIR.
SO IT'S BEEN COOLING
FOR A LITTLE WHILE,
AND WE HAVE OUR COOKED RICE.
I'M GONNA MIX THIS UP
BY HAND.
NO BINDER, HUH? JUST THE RICE
IS GONNA WORK ENOUGH.
THAT AND THE FAT OF THE--
THE RICE AND THE FAT.
AND THAT'S IT.
INTERESTING.
THESE GO GREAT WITH BEER,
BY THE WAY.
NO. WHO WOULD THINK THAT?
THEN WE DREDGE 'EM
IN SOME FLOUR
AND SOME--
THEN BUTTERMILK
SETS UP ON THE FLOUR.
AND BREADCRUMBS.
NON-SALTED BREADCRUMB.
YEP, NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
AND WE'LL FRY THESE
AT 350 DEGREES?
4 TO 5 MINUTES.
BROWN UP ON THE OUTSIDE...
OUTSIDE.
BECAUSE IT'S ALREADY COOKED.
ONTO MY LITTLE PAPER
AND ONTO THE PLATE.
AND A LITTLE PARSLEY GARNISH.
THERE THEY GO.
CRACKING INTO IT,
IT'S LIKE A HILI BALL.
MMM. WOW.
THERE IS SO MUCH FLAVOR.
YOU DID A NICE JOB
WITH HOW YOU FRIED IT.
IT'S NOT OILY BY ANY MEANS.
THE RICE WASN'T OVERCOOKED,
SO IT STAYS TENDER.
I THINK YOU'D REALLY SURPRISE
PEOPLE WITH THIS.
HERE'S YOUR FRITTERS.
GOOD TEXTURE TO IT,
GOOD ZING.
ONE ORDER OF BOUDIN.
THE RICE IS VERY FRESH,
AND IT'S A LITTLE TANGY TO IT.
THE FLAVORS ALL COMPLEMENT
EACH OTHER.
TABLE 12.
ALL THE FOOD IS VERY, VERY GOOD.
TWO LOW COUNTRY BOILS.
WHATEVER'S ON THE MENU,
I KNOW THAT WE'RE ALL
GONNA HAVE A GREAT MEAL.
GOOD ENERGY, NICE PEOPLE.
PLEASURE TO SEE YA.
YOU HAPPY?
I AM.
GOOD DEAL.
YOU GOT IT GOING, MAN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NEXT STOP,
WE'RE HEADING TO D.C...
THIS IS THE YALIE.
FOR PIES AND PADDLE.
DO YOU RUN INTO A LOT
OF PING-PONG RESTAURANTS?
NO, THIS IS THE FIRST.
ON TRIPLE "D," WE'VE SHOT
AT A GAS STATION.
WE'VE SHOT AT A CAR WASH.
SHOT AT A BOWLING ALLEY.
I MEAN, WE'VE EVEN SHOT
IN THE BACK OF A LIQUOR STORE.
SO JUST WHEN
YOU MIGHT BE THINKING,
AH, THEY'RE RUNNING OUT
OF CRAZY PLACES TO SHOOT,
HERE WE ARE IN NORTHWEST
WASHINGTON, D.C.,
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT'S
SERVING UP PING-PONG AND PIZZA.
THIS IS COMET PING PONG.
DO YOU RUN INTO A LOT
OF PING-PONG RESTAURANTS?
NO, THIS IS THE FIRST.
FUN ATMOSPHERE,
GREAT PIZZA.
(woman) YOUR SMOKY'S HERE.
SMOKY BACON, SMOKY MUSHROOMS
AND A SMOKED MOZZARELLA.
(man) ONE SOFTY COMING UP.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB PIZZA.
MMM. THAT'S A FIRST, MAN.
COMING UP.
AND IT'S ALL COOKED UP
BY OWNER JAMES ALEFANTIS...
2 PIES FOR 25.
WHO'S BEEN IN THE BIZ
SINCE HE WAS 15.
I GREW UP, LIKE, BAKING.
PLUS I LOVE PLAYING PING-PONG.
SO, OF COURSE, IT MADE SENSE
TO PUT THE TWO TOGETHER...
GOURMET-TYPE OF PIZZA IN
A VERY LAID-BACK TYPE OF PLACE.
STARTING WITH A HOMEMADE CRUST.
LET'S GET THIS GOING.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE TAKE CAPUTO,
ITALIAN FLOUR,
HIGH GLUTEN, REALLY SILKY,
WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR...
SO A LITTLE COLOR,
A LITTLE TEXTURE.
A BUNCH OF SALT,
DRY YEAST.
STRAIGHT IN.
NOTHING ELSE.
WE HAVE A SECRET INGREDIENT,
DIAGNOSTIC MALT POWDER.
REALLY?
IT HELPS WITH THE RISE.
IT ADDS A LITTLE BIT
OF CHEW TO IT.
WATER.
ROOM TEMPERATURE?
YEAH. THAT'S IT.
COMBINE IT, THREE MINUTES.
AND THEN KICK IT UP
ANOTHER LEVEL?
YEAH, AND THEN IT GOES
FOR THREE MORE.
IT'S DONE.
PULL IT OUT.
YOU'RE GOING INTO
A FLOURED 5-GALLON BUCKET.
WE STICK THIS IN THE WALK-IN
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.,
AND THEN IT'LL BE READY
IN A COUPLE HOURS.
RISES UP.
YOU PUNCH IT DOWN TWICE
AND THEN BRING IT OUT
AND PORTION IT.
YEP.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO YOU JUST BALLPARK IT
IN THERE.
YEAH.
SHAPE IT UP.
LET IT REST.
TAKE THESE GUYS OUT OF HERE.
THEY'VE RISEN FOR A WHILE.
SILKY DOUGH.
WE'LL ROLL OUT.
NICE AND STRETCHY.
NICE.
SEMOLINA.
PUT IT ON THE PALLET.
HOW'S THAT FOR A ROOK?
GORGEOUS.
AND THEY'RE LOADING 'EM
WITH EVERYTHING FROM EGGS...
I LIKE IT.
TO ARUGULA, EVEN CLAMS
ON THEIR BEST-SELLING YALIE.
WHY DO YOU CALL IT YALIE?
PART OF THIS RESTAURANT
WAS INSPIRED BY
NEW HAVEN, CONNECTICUT.
YALE. NEW HAVEN.
SO WE TAKE
OUR LITTLENECK CLAMS.
POUR 'EM INTO HERE
INTO A DRY SKILLET.
AWESOME SOUND.
GET IT HOT. LET 'EM COOK.
BUNCH OF WHOLE GARLIC, LEMONS,
THEN WE GOT FRESH THYME,
A BUNCH OF OLIVE OIL.
AND JUST LET 'EM GO.
AS SOON AS
THEY START POPPING OPEN.
GIVE IT A STIR.
POUR 'EM OUT.
SHUCK 'EM OUT
FOR THE PIZZAS.
ONE FOR ME. MMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES IT
IS THE THYME.
DON'T EAT
ALL THESE CLAMS, MAN.
WE GOT TO MAKE SOME PIZZAS.
OH, THOSE ARE GOOD.
HERE WE GOT THE YALIE,
COMING UP.
SALT...
RIGHT ON THE DOUGH.
A LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER,
SOME OF THESE
SLOW-COOKED ONIONS,
GARLIC OIL--
GARLIC THAT'S BEEN SLICED
AND COOKED DOWN VERY SLOWLY--
FRESH THYME.
I JUST GET THE CLAMS AND--
SHUCK 'EM ON THERE.
USUALLY DO TEN. THAT LOOKS GOOD.
THAT'S THE WAY IT GOES.
YEP, STICK IT ON IN.
GETTING WAY BACK.
OH, LOVE THIS!
THE AVERAGE TIME TO COOK
IN THAT OVEN?
JUST ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
LOOK HOW FAST IT COMES UP.
OH.
YALIE UP.
LOOK AT THE CRUST RIGHT
ON THE BOTTOM OF THAT THING.
ADD A LITTLE LEMON.
MMM. OH!
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW.
OUTSTANDING. EVERYTHING WORKS.
THE DOUGH'S ON POINT,
THE TEMPERATURE.
YOU DON'T EVEN NOTICE
THERE'S NO CHEESE,
'CAUSE THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS
ARE JUST MELTING ON THERE.
MMM!
I CAN'T EAT THIS FAST ENOUGH.
I WILL FIGHT YOU
FOR THE REST OF THAT.
THIS IS THE YALIE.
IT'S GREAT.
THE BEST PIZZA IN D.C.
(woman) YOUR PIE'S HERE.
IT'S REALLY FRESH,
LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
(James) SPINACH.
FROM LOCAL FARMS.
MUSHROOM AND ONION.
IT'S AS FARM TO TABLE
AS YOU CAN GET IT.
OH, YEAH.
WE HARVEST 4,000 POUNDS
OF ORGANIC TOMATOES EVERY YEAR.
CAN 'EM.
AND WE GOT ONE WHOLE YEAR
OF SAUCE.
GREAT SWEETNESS.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
WE CRAFT EVERYTHING.
EVEN THE RICOTTA.
ALL YOU DO IS TAKE A GALLON
OF MILK, A GALLON OF BUTTERMILK.
WANT ME TO GIVE YOU
SOME MILK WITH THAT?
THAT'D BE GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA CHUG
THE BUTTERMILK. GO, GO, GO!
WHOO-HOO! SOMEONE'S GONNA
NEED TO CLEAN THAT UP.
WHOO!
WHO'S CLEANIN' THAT UP?!
AND THE ACTIVATION
OF THE BUTTERMILK ALONE
IS WHAT TAKES CARE
OF THAT MILK.
YOU JUST SEE
IT STARTS TO PULL AWAY.
SEPARATING, YEAH.
YEAH.
THE CURD AND THE WHEY.
THEN WE STRAIN IT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, WHILE WE'RE
WATCHING THIS, WE GO...
PLAY SOME PING-PONG?
EAT SOME CLAMS.
HA! NO!
PUT THIS CHEESECLOTH
IN HERE.
TAKE THIS RICOTTA,
LET IT SEPARATE OUT.
GRAB THIS BABY
OUT OF THIS WATER.
SQUEEZE IT ENOUGH
TO TELL THE WATER
IT'S SUPPOSED TO COME OUT.
LET IT COOL?
JUST LIKE 15 MINUTES.
SO THIS PIZZA'S CALLED
THE STANLEY, NAMED AFTER
THE SAUSAGE MAKER WHO HELPED US
MAKE THE FENNEL SAUSAGES.
SALT, PEPPER, SAUCE,
A FEW KINDS OF MOZZARELLA,
ROASTED PEPPERS.
THIS IS THE FENNEL SAUSAGE
MADE WITH VIRGINIA-RAISED
HEIRLOOM PORK
MIXED WITH FENNEL
AND HOT PEPPER.
THEN WE CAN SEE
HOW OUR RICOTTA TURNED OUT.
MMM.
NICE AND CREAMY AND LIGHT--
DYNAMITE.
THAT'S IT.
INTO THE OVEN.
THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
600 DEGREES ON THE DECK.
MMM.
SLOWLY, TILL IT MELTS OUT.
THAT RICOTTA'S NUTS, MAN.
WOW.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
OHH! OUTSTANDING.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO TELL YOU, MAN.
ALL THE COMPONENTS--
RICOTTA TIGHTENED UP NICE.
IT'S FIRM AND LIGHT.
THE ROASTED PEPPER SAUCE
IS GREAT.
THIS IS ROCK STAR
ALL THE WAY.
(man) STANLEY UP.
IT'S REALLY TO DIE FOR.
MMM. IT'S LIGHT. IT'S FRESH.
2 PIES FOR 25.
NOT YOUR TYPICAL
CHEESE AND TOMATO SAUCE.
AND THIS
AIN'T YOUR TYPICAL CALZONE...
PHILLY UP.
STUFFED, ROLLED
AND ROASTED FRESH PORK...
THIS IS CRAZY!
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM!
AT COMET PING PONG
IN WASHINGTON, D.C...
THIS IS THE SOFTY.
THANK YOU.
FANS ARE KEEPING
THE TABLES PACKED.
YOU CAN PLAY PING-PONG WHILE
YOU'RE WAITING FOR YOUR PIZZA.
IT'S GREAT.
AND OWNER JAMES ALEFANTIS
IS CRACKING OUT
15 ORIGINAL PIES...
YOU GOT A JIMMY WITH THAT.
AND HIS FAVORITE CALZONE.
HERE, I GOT A PHILLY UP.
TO DIE FOR.
IT'S CALLED A PHILLY
'CAUSE IT WAS BASED ON
A PHILADELPHIA
TRADITIONAL SANDWICH.
WELL, LOOSELY BASED.
IT STARTS WITH THIS--
A WHOLE
BUTTERFLIED PORK LOIN.
BEAUTIFUL.
OKAY. NICE WHITE TO THAT.
SEASON IT UP--
SALT, PEPPER,
HOT PEPPERS--
'CAUSE THAT'S PHILLY STYLE--
A BUNCH OF PARSLEY,
A BUNCH OF CHOPPED GARLIC...
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE GOING
WITH IT.
OLIVE OIL--
THAT'S THE EASY PART.
THE TOUGHER PART...
PUT IT BACK TOGETHER
THE WAY IT WAS.
FOLD IT RIGHT BACK OVER.
(whistles)
SOME SALT, PEPPER,
PARSLEY ON THE OUTSIDE,
OLIVE OIL.
LOOKS GREAT.
YOU WON'T LOSE
WITH THAT LOIN.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
TIE THIS GUY OFF.
YOU GOT IT?
YEAH.
SO NOW THIS GOES IN...
THE PIZZA OVEN.
UNTIL IT GETS A NICE CRUST.
YEP.
IT'S SO HOT THAT
IT JUST CHARS UP ALL THE FAT.
THEN YOU PULL IT OUT,
FINISH IT OFF...
IN THE CONVENTIONAL OVEN.
GET IT UP
TO WHAT TEMPERATURE?
THE MEAT WE DO TO 160,
AND WHEN IT COMES OUT OF
THAT OVEN, THE SKIN IS GORGEOUS.
NICE AND CARAMELIZED
ON THE TOP.
MMM!
I'M SORRY.
THAT'S NOT FANTASTIC.
THIS IS GOING INTO WHAT?
THIS GOES INSIDE
OF A CALZONE--THE PHILLY.
THE PHILLY-ME-UP.
YEP.
LET'S DO IT.
LET'S DO IT UP.
SALT, TINY BIT OF PEPPER.
THEN A NICE BASE.
I LOVE THIS GARLIC OIL.
ROASTED PIECES OF PORK--
LAY THEM OUT
INSIDE OF YOUR CALZONE.
WE DO BROCCOLI RABE--
SAUTé IT UP--
GARLIC, SALT, LEMON ZEST.
STICK THOSE IN THERE.
THEN TAKE SOME SLICES
OF PROVOLONE CHEESE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S IT.
SO YOU TAKE THAT GUY,
WRAP IT UP LIKE THIS,
TRADITIONALLY FOLD IT OVER.
A LITTLE HOLE IN IT
SO IT DOESN'T STEAM UP...
YEP.
CREATE A DOME, BECOME DRY
AND CRACK OFF.
NOT GOOD.
STICK IT IN THE OVEN.
NOW HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
IN THE OVEN?
IT TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
READY? LOOKS GOOD.
(whistles)
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKIN'
'ZONE.
SOME SAUCE IF YOU WANT.
MMM!
OUT OF BOUNDS, MAN.
THE ROAST PORK IS CRAZY.
THE WOOD-FIRED
PIZZA OVEN DOUGH--
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
PICK YOUR OWN TOMATOES,
AND CAN 'EM--FRESH AND SWEET.
MMM! QUALITY
REAL INGREDIENTS.
THIS IS HOW IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE DONE.
IF YOU LIVE NORTH
OF THE EQUATOR,
YOU HAVE TO COME UP HERE.
I MEAN, THERE'S JUST NO EXCUSE.
ANYBODY SOUTH,
YOU HAVE AN EXTRA DAY.
THIS IS THE PHILLY.
VERY SMOKY FLAVORS.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
(man) COMING AROUND.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
AND THE PING-PONG
IS FUN.
CALZONE, PIZZA,
YOU NAME IT.
THIS IS SOME OF THE BEST PIZZA
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
BROTHER, I'VE HAD A BLAST.
THANK YOU. AWESOME JOB.
THANK YOU.
WHAT A GREAT ROAD TRIP.
BUT DON'T WORRY, WE GOT PLENTY
MORE PLACES TO CHECK OUT.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
CULINARY NAPALM,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU GET THIS ON YOU,
AND YOU ARE NOT GONNA FORGET
WHERE IT WENT.
YOU COULD WAX WITH THIS.
(laughter)