HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU WROTE THE E-MAIL?
YOU CALLED IT.
WHY DID YOU WANT ME
TO COME HERE?
IT'S OFF THE HOOK.
IN FRANKFORT, KENTUCKY...
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING
LIKE THIS ANYWHERE ELSE.
THE LOCAL DIVE
WHERE FOLKS ARE DIVIN' IN
FOR PO BOYS...
I'D EAT THAT
EVERY DAY. WOW.
AND CRAWFISH PIE.
MMM. I LOVE IT.
IN CLOQUET, MINNESOTA...
THEIR BURGERS
ARE JUST REALLY GOOD.
THE 50-YEAR-OLD
FAN FAVORITE...
HI. WHAT CAN
I GET YOU?
WHERE SERVIN' UP
THE CLASSICS...
BACON CHEESEBURGER UP.
MEANS MORE THAN 200,000
AWESOME PATTIES A YEAR.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT
THE ALL-AMERICAN DRIVE-IN,
THAT'S THE BURGER
THEY'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
AND IN
FOUNTAIN VALLEY, CALIFORNIA...
HASH BROWNS
ON THE S.O.S.
THE MILITARY COFFEE SHOP...
THERE'S ALWAYS
A TON OF VETS IN HERE.
WHERE FOLKS ARE MARCHIN' IN...
S.O.S. GOIN' OUT.
FOR A MESS...
PREPARE TO EAT.
OF MESS HALL FAVORITES.
EAT.
MMM. IT'S A "SEMPER FI-NER"
DINER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
ON I64, RIGHT BETWEEN
LOUISVILLE AND LEXINGTON,
IS KENTUCKY STATE CAPITAL
FRANKFORT.
NOW WHEN YOU COME OVER
THE SINGIN' BRIDGE HERE
INTO THE SOUTH SIDE,
YOU'LL SEE THIS LITTLE
67-YEAR-OLD JOINT
THAT'S OWNED
BY ONE UNIQUE CHARACTER.
I HEAR YOU TAKE
A SEAT AT THIS PLACE,
YOU WON'T FORGET IT.
THIS IS
RICK'S WHITE LIGHT DINER.
COME ON IN.
I'LL TELL YA WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA EAT HERE.
CUPCAKES.
NO, I DON'T THINK SO.
IT'S AN EVENT COMING
IN HERE JUST FOR LUNCH.
COME AGAIN.
I CALL IT LUNCH
AND A SHOW.
REALLY? YOU WANT SOME
MARMALADE WITH THAT?
HE'S SUCH A CHARACTER.
THAT'D BE OWNER
RICK PAUL...
EAT UP.
WHO GAVE UP FINE DINING...
CHEERS.
WHEN HE FELL IN LOVE
WITH THIS PLACE...
THEY HAD AN AUCTION.
THEY WERE GONNA
STRIP THE JOINT.
THEY WERE GONNA STRIP IT.
YOU BOUGHT THE WHOLE THING?
YEAH.
AND STARTED COOKIN'
ONLY WHAT HE FELT LIKE MAKIN'.
WE GOT A LIMITED
MENU HERE.
BUT THAT DOESN'T STOP FOLKS
FROM JAMMIN' THE JOINT...
HOW'S EVERYBODY
DOIN' OUT HERE?
OR TELLIN' ME
TO COME CHECK IT OUT.
WHAT MAKES THE JOINT
SO GOOD, DO YOU THINK?
THE FOOD IS PERFECT.
'CAUSE I WATCH YOUR SHOW, AND I
JUST THOUGHT THIS WOULD BE
A PERFECT PLACE.
AND ON THE MENU TODAY,
EVERYTHING
FROM A CHICKEN QUESADILLA...
THIS IS JUST AMAZING.
TO AN OYSTER PO BOY...
IT WAS DELICIOUS.
AND LOUISIANA
CRAWFISH PIE.
MMM. THAT'S DELICIOUS.
I'M GONNA MAKE A PIE SHELL
HERE FOR THE CRAWFISH PIE.
FLOUR. THIS IS
A BASIC RECIPE.
SIMPLE. SALT.
JUST A PINCH. IT SHOULD CUT
LIKE THE COLDEST ICE CREAM
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
HECK OF A BUTTER RATIO, BOSS.
YEAH.
ARE YOU FINGER ACTUATING
THIS THING?
WELL, I'M CONTROLLING
THE SPEED.
THIS IS AMAZING.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
COLD WATER.
WE'RE NOT MEASURING,
BUT WE'RE GONNA WATCH.
TILL IT JUST STARTS
TO PULL AWAY FROM THE SIDE.
I'D SAY YOU'RE THERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
TAKE THIS ONE
AND WORK IT
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
THOSE ARE LITTLE
CHUNKS OF BUTTER.
IT'S BEEN SO COLD
THAT IT DIDN'T BREAK UP,
AND THAT'S GONNA CREATE
THIS INCREDIBLE FLAKINESS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYBODY MAKE ONE SQUARE.
(laughs)
I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO MAKE IT ROUND.
I HAVE NO IDEA,
AND I DON'T CARE.
THE SHELL IS DONE.
NOW WE GOT TO MAKE
THE FILLING.
RIGHT.
THIS IS NOT AN EXACT SCIENCE
ON THIS ONE.
I WOULDN'T
EXPECT IT TO BE.
YOU BARELY FOLLOW EXACT SCIENCE
ON MAKING PIECRUST.
BUTTER, ONIONS, RED BELL PEPPER,
JUST THROW 'EM IN.
THESE ARE FARM-RAISED
CRAWFISH TAILS.
GARLIC'S GOING IN.
WOW, BIG CHUNKS
OF GARLIC.
THAT'S HOW I EAT IT.
I LIKE THAT.
TONY'S SEASONING,
BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE COMINO?
CUMIN, YEAH.
SPRING ONIONS.
THESE ARE...
CHIPOTLES?
YEAH.
WE'RE JUST GONNA PUT
A LITTLE FLOUR IN THERE.
A LITTLE ROUX.
THAT'S GONNA BE A LIGHT ONE.
I ALWAYS JUST SORT OF
LOOK AT IT AS I GO.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE ADD
SOME HEAVY CREAM.
MIX THAT UP.
THAT RIGHT THERE IS IT.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE GO RIGHT TO THE PIE SHELL.
LOOK AT THAT, MAN.
SO CRUST ON TOP OF THIS THING
AND THEN A FEW SLITS.
WE'RE GONNA BRUSH THE TOP
WITH SOME EGG YOLK.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SHEEN.
BAKE IT OFF.
RIGHT.
SHE READY, BOSS?
IT LOOKS READY.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
COMING OUT. THAT'S IT.
ME, OH, MY.
YEAH, THIS IS NICE.
LOOK AT THAT BIG OLD CHUNK
OF GARLIC.
MMM.
BLAND?
YOU CAN'T EVEN SPELL BLAND.
(laughs)
THAT DOESN'T EVEN EXIST
IN YOUR DICTIONARY.
OH, THAT'S GOOD, MAN.
THE CRAWFISH,
THE VEGETABLES--MMM--
I LOVE THE BIG CHUNKS
OF GARLIC.
I GOT TO TELL YA
HOW REMARKABLE THE CRUST IS.
YOUR BUTTER-TO-FLOUR RATIO
IS RIGHT--A NOTCH BELOW INSANE.
THANK YOU.
I LOVE IT.
(woman) HERE'S
YOUR CRAWFISH PIE.
IT'S SPICY AND YUMMY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THIS?
LOVE IT. LOVE IT.
CRAB CAKE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET THE BEST FOOD
FROM RICK.
DOES THAT LOOK GOOD?
(woman) HE BELIEVES
IN ORGANIC.
GOT IT.
HE KNOWS EXACTLY WHERE
HE'S GETTING HIS FOOD FROM.
AND HIS BREAD...
OYSTER PO BOY.
THAT COMES STRAIGHT
OUT OF HIS OWN OVEN.
YOU MAKE FRENCH BREAD
EVERY DAY...
MM-HMM. YES.
REALLY? THAT'S AWESOME.
USUALLY RUN OUT.
ALL IT IS IS FLOUR, SALT,
A LITTLE BIT OF HONEY.
THIS HONEY CAME FROM MY SISTER
IN WEST VIRGINIA.
A LITTLE YEAST
SETUP THERE.
YEAST AND WATER RIGHT HERE.
IT'S A WONDERFUL RECIPE
BECAUSE IT IS SIMPLE.
TOWEL ON IT, LET IT SET UP
A LITTLE BIT.
GOT IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FORM IT
INTO LOAVES OF BREAD.
LOAVES.
I'M GONNA GET FOUR
OUT OF THIS.
ARE YOU REALLY?
CORNMEAL.
WHAT TEMP ARE
WE GONNA BAKE THESE AT, BOSS?
ABOUT 350.
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT'S IT SET AT?
(speaking indistinctly)
OH, THAT SMELLS AWESOME.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'LL RISE UP.
SET IT RIGHT BACK HERE.
HOW WE LOOKING?
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
AND THERE WE GO
IN THE OVEN.
PROBABLY BE 15, 20 MINUTES.
REALLY, THAT QUICK?
WHAT ARE WE ONTO, BOSS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A DREDGE FOR THE OYSTERS.
CORNMEAL, FLOUR,
THERE YOU GO.
AND BLACK PEPPER.
GARLIC POWDER,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
WHOA, THAT'S A LOT
OF CAYENNE.
THESE ARE GONNA BE
SOME SPICY ONES.
GET READY.
TONY'S SEASONING.
STIR IT UP.
LET'S GO.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
STIR THESE UP.
LET THEM INDIVIDUALLY COAT.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH BREADING,
THEN I GUARANTEE YOU
THAT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
LITTLE BITTY PIECES
OF BREADING ON HERE,
AND IT'S GONNA BE HORRIBLE.
GOT TO HAVE NICE
DRY BREADING.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT--NICE
FRESH OYSTER, EVENLY COATED.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA FRY 'EM IN?
PEANUT OIL.
WE'RE GONNA FRY THESE
FOR ABOUT FIVE SECONDS.
JUST ENOUGH TO MAKE
A CRUST.
HERE WE GO.
LET'S SEE THAT BREAD.
LOOK AT THAT.
THEY ALL LOOK DIFFERENT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA EAT
SOME OF THIS.
LOOK AT THAT,
NICE AND WARM, MOIST. MMM.
I GRILL THE OUTSIDE
OF THE BREAD,
BUT IT'S SOFT
ON THE INSIDE.
THE OYSTERS ARE READY.
OKAY, CHIPOTLE PEPPER SAUCE.
MAYONNAISE, OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, CHIPOTLE PEPPERS.
PURéE IT. DONE.
LOOKING GOOD. COOL.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME CHIPOTLE PEPPER SAUCE.
THAT LOOKS GOOD LIKE THAT.
BOOM. BOOM.
THERE IS AN OYSTER PO BOY.
LOOK AT THE LOAD ON THAT.
MMM.
IT'S GOT GREAT CRUNCH.
THE BREAD TASTE ON THE OUTSIDE
IS AWESOME.
YOU DEFINITELY PUT SOME HEAT
ON THIS WITH THAT CHIPOTLE. MMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT THE OYSTERS?
YOU LET THAT BREADING GET HOT,
WHICH JUST PUT A LITTLE CRISP
ON THAT.
MMM. I'D EAT THAT EVERY DAY.
WOW.
I JUST LOVE
EVERYTHING ABOUT IT.
YOU CAN'T GET ANYTHING LIKE THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
(Paul) CRAWFISH PIE.
IT'S AUTHENTIC SOUTHERN COOKING
AT ITS FINEST.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS REALLY
WHAT THE SHOW'S ABOUT.
YOU GUYS FIND
THESE FUNKY JOINTS.
YOU WRITE IN.
YOU TELL ME ABOUT IT.
I CHECK IT OUT,
AND AMERICA GETS
A LITTLE INTRODUCTION ON
ONE OF THE GREATEST PLACES.
I MEAN, THIS PLACE
IS OFF THE CHAIN.
IT IS.
IS THIS HOT?
(Guy) THIS HAS BEEN HYSTERICAL
AND DELICIOUS.
I GOT TO TELL YOU SOMETHING,
BROTHER, I HAVE HAD A BLAST.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE THE BEST.
I APPRECIATE IT.
I REALLY ENJOYED IT.
YOU GOT TO MEET THIS GUY.
AMAZING.
UP NEXT...
CHEESEBURGER AND AN ORDER
OF ONION RINGS, PLEASE.
WE'RE HEADING TO MINNESOTA...
IT'S GOT A NOSTALGIC FLAVOR.
MMM.
AND BACK IN TIME.
THEY'RE STILL DOING IT
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY,
MAKING THE PATTIES
BY HAND.
TRIPLE "D" IN HISTORY.
I MEAN, IT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
I LOVE ABOUT THIS SHOW.
IT'S FINDING THE JOINTS
THAT HAVE BEEN DOING IT
OLD-SCHOOL FOR GENERATIONS.
SO HERE WE ARE ABOUT 20 MILES
SOUTH OF DULUTH, MINNESOTA,
OFF INTERSTATE 35 IN
A LUMBER TOWN CALLED CLOQUET.
NOW CHECK IT OUT.
THESE FOLKS HAVE BEEN ROCKING
OVER 11 1/2 MILLION
BURGER PATTIES
SINCE THEY OPENED IN 1960.
AND HERE'S THE KICKER.
THEY'RE ONLY OPEN SIX MONTHS
OUT OF THE YEAR.
YOU WROTE IN ABOUT IT. WE'RE
HERE. THIS IS GORDY'S HI-HAT.
BACON CHEESEBURGER UP.
YOU WROTE THE E-MAIL?
WHY'D YOU WANT ME TO COME HERE?
'CAUSE IT'S OFF THE HOOK.
(woman) MUSHROOM AND SWISS.
DID YOU WRITE IN TO ME?
A COUPLE TIMES.
AND YOU LIKE IT,
'CAUSE IT'S OLD-SCHOOL.
THEY'RE STILL DOING IT
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY,
MAKING THE PATTIES
BY HAND.
TWO HAMBURGERS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE BURGER IS ALWAYS
SO JUICY AND GOOD.
HAND PATTY EVERY DAY.
15 TON OF 'EM.
THAT'S ABOUT A TON A WEEK.
IT'S BEEN THAT WAY
SINCE GORDY LUNDQUIST...
CAN I HELP YOU?
AND HIS WIFE MARILYN...
ORDER UP.
OPENED THE PLACE
50 YEARS AGO...
(man) BACON DELUXE.
AND WHEN SON DAN TOOK OVER...
HI. WHAT CAN I GET YA?
HE KNEW BETTER THAN TO MESS
WITH TRADITION.
DOUBLE CHEESE
WITH THE WORKS.
WHAT'S THE NUMBER ONE
SELLING ITEM ON THE MENU?
DOUBLE CHEESEBURGERS WITH
MARILYN ON THE GRILL, MY MOM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
WITH ALL THESE PATTIES?
PUT ALL THOSE PATTIES ON.
I HEARD THAT YOU RUN THIS
BETTER THAN ANYBODY.
I DO.
I DUMP ALL THE ONIONS.
ONIONS ARE JUST SITTING HERE
ALL THE TIME TO GO?
ALL THE TIME.
THEN WE HAVE OUR PEPPER AND SALT
MIXED TOGETHER.
HEALTHY WITH THAT, HUH?
THEN I START FLIPPIN' 'EM.
JUST KEEP PUTTING--
AS SOON AS THEY GO ON,
YOU'RE ALREADY STARTING
TO FLIP 'EM AND...
I FLIP 'EM RIGHT AWAY.
HOW MANY TIMES
DO YOU FLIP 'EM?
JUST A COUPLE TIMES.
AND WE'LL PUT A BUN ON--
THEY GET IT AS THEY WANT 'EM.
IF THEY DON'T WANT MUSTARD
OR WHATEVER ELSE.
WHAT ABOUT THOSE ONIONS?
PUT SOME ONIONS ON.
LIKE YOUR CHEESE MELTED?
PLEASE.
WE ALWAYS MELT THE CHEESE--
A COUPLE PICKLES.
SO IT GETS ALL BUILT
RIGHT ON THERE.
IT'S ALL BUILT ON THERE,
AND THEN I JUST
PUT IT ON THE BUN.
THE BUN TOPS ARE TOASTED, AND WE
PUT IT INTO THE CONTAINER.
AND THIS IS THE NUMBER ONE
SELLER?
THE NUMBER ONE
BEST SELLER.
MMM, THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
WHEN YOU COOK A BURGER
ON A FLATTOP,
IT BUILDS A LITTLE CRUST.
THEN WHEN YOU MELT
AMERICAN CHEESE ON IT,
IT GETS A CREAMINESS ABOUT IT.
LOOK AT ALL THAT JUICE.
IF YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT
THE ALL-AMERICAN DRIVE-IN,
THAT'S THE KIND OF BURGER
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
YOU MAKE IT YOURSELVES.
YOU'VE BEEN DOING IT THAT WAY
FOR 50 YEARS. YOU'RE AWESOME.
50 YEARS. AWESOME.
CHEESEBURGER TO GO.
OH, MAN,
THESE CHEESEBURGERS ARE GREAT.
THE BEEF IS INCREDIBLE.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
DOUBLE CHEESE.
THE BURGERS
ARE JUST REALLY GOOD.
427.
EVER EAT HERE
TWICE IN A DAY?
OH, YEAH.
BUT IN THE MINNESOTA WINTER,
YOU CAN'T EAT HERE AT ALL.
IT'S CLOSED
SIX MONTHS OUT OF THE YEAR.
I KNOW.
YOU GUYS SHOULD
PUT A MOOSE OUT FRONT,
TELL PEOPLE THE PARK'S CLOSED
FOR THE SEASON.
IT'S HUGE WHEN THEY OPEN.
AND AFTER SIX MONTHS
OF WAITING...
CHEESEBURGER AND AN ORDER
OF ONION RINGS, PLEASE.
GORDY'S CUSTOMERS
KNOW WHAT THEY WANT.
FISH SANDWICH, THE MUSHROOM
AND SWISS AND THE ONION RINGS.
NEED A RING, PLEASE.
THE ONION RINGS
ARE THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
WE DO ONION RINGS
EVERY DAY.
THAT'S A BIG ONION.
LOOK AT YOU
GO AFTER IT.
WE USUALLY DO A FINGER
LIKE THIS FOR A RING, OKAY?
YEAH, I'M CRYING.
OH, IT'S FUNNY, HUH?
I'M JUST SAD, BECAUSE I DON'T
HAVE A GORDY'S NEXT TO MY HOUSE.
WE THROW SOME IN THE BUTTERMILK,
AND THIS IS THE BREADING.
CORNMEAL?
IT'S A CORNMEAL.
THEN THIS IS THE PANCAKE MIX.
STRAIGHT-UP PANCAKE MIX?
YEAH, IT GOES IN A SECOND COAT
OF BREADING.
AND THAT'S IT.
YEP.
IT JUST HOLDS
RIGHT ON THERE.
YOU CAN DROP 'EM IN,
AND THE GREASE IS ABOUT 375.
WHEN THEY'RE DONE, THEY SHOULD
BE NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
OKAY,
AND THESE
GET SERVED WITH...
WE JUST SERVE 'EM
WITH CATSUP.
WITH WHAT?
CATSUP.
I THINK
THAT MEANS KETCHUP.
IS THIS HOW YOU DO IT
RIGHT HERE?
PERFECT.
OH, THOSE ARE GREAT.
AWESOME, AWESOME.
YOU GET A REAL ONION FLAVOR,
INCREDIBLE CRUNCH.
KILLER.
LOOK AT THAT.
FRIED THE RIGHT WAY,
NOT OVERSEASONED,
AND WHEN YOU EAT IT WITH SOME
CATSUP, THEY'RE REALLY GOOD.
TWO RINGS AND A FRY.
THE ONION RINGS
ARE THE BEST.
CRISPY, NOT GREASY,
THEY'RE FRESH.
I NEED A RING.
THE BATTER IS AMAZING,
HOMEMADE EVERY DAY.
ONION RINGS.
OKAY.
THE FOOD IS WONDERFUL.
IT'S A VERY CLASSIC DINER.
PROUD TO HAVE KEPT
A CLASSIC MENU.
BURGER IS UP.
BURGER, FRIES AND A SHAKE
EVERY TIME.
BLACKBERRY AND RASPBERRY.
LET ME JUST HELP YOU OUT
WITH THAT.
ROAST BEEF SANDWICH UP.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
IT'S A FAMILY TRADITION.
AND SO IS THIS...
NOTHING BETTER
THAN A HOT BOWL OF CHILI.
A FAMILY RECIPE THAT HASN'T
CHANGED IN HALF A CENTURY.
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS AN OLD RECIPE
WE'VE BEEN MAKING FOREVER,
AND FIRST
I'M GONNA START WITH...
WHIPPED BUTTER?
WHIPPED BUTTER.
THEN WE DUMP
OUR FRESHLY CUT CELERY.
ALL IN ONE?
ALL IN ONE.
WHAT'S GOING ON
OVER HERE?
GREEN PEPPERS OVER THERE.
COMING IN.
LID GOES ON.
SO SWEAT 'EM
LIKE THAT.
AND THEN WE SWEAT 'EM
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT TOGETHER
OUR CHILI SAUCE.
JUST STRAIGHT-UP OLD CHILI SAUCE
LIKE YOU BUY, OKAY.
CHILI SAUCE
LIKE YOU BUY.
FRESH TOMATOES,
I HAVE KIDNEY BEANS.
NEED SOME HELP
ON THAT ONE?
I MIGHT HAVE SOME HELP,
HONEY.
HERE WE GO.
JUICE AND ALL?
JUICE AND ALL,
CHILI POWDER.
I'M GONNA STIR THAT UP,
AND WE'RE GOING TO ADD
OUR SAUTéED CELERY--
LOTS OF CELERY--
AND THE GREEN PEPPER.
AND WE'VE GOT THE 10 POUNDS
OF MEAT THAT WE GROUND
WITH OUR ONIONS
ON OUR GRILL.
KEEP SCOOPING.
DO YOU LIKE CHILI?
I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU GET YOURS?
I JUST GET IT
STRAIGHT UP.
YOU DID A GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
I'M GLAD I GOT TO PLAY.
SO WHERE IS THIS
GONNA COOK AT?
IT GOES INTO A BIG CONTAINER
WHERE IT'S KEPT HOT UP FRONT.
CHILI IS READY.
BOWL OF CHILI.
WOW, THAT'S THICK.
SOME ONIONS, CHEESE, DO YOU WANT
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE?
HIT IT.
NOW YOU'RE TALKING TO ME.
MMM, IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A SWEETNESS TO IT.
AS A KID,
THAT'S WHY I LIKED IT SO MUCH,
BECAUSE IT WAS SWEET.
I THINK IT'S THE CHILI SAUCE
AND THE MEAT, THE ONION--
THE SWEET AND THE HEAT.
THAT MAKES YOU HAPPY.
IT'S GOT A NOSTALGIC FLAVOR.
THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT.
LOAD IT RIGHT UP. MMM.
THAT'S JUST GOOD, ALL-AMERICAN,
STRAIGHTFORWARD CHILI.
BOWL OF CHILI IS UP.
IT IS GREAT CHILI.
IT'S REAL THICK--
BEANS AND CHEESE--VERY GOOD.
TWO CHILI TO GO.
IT'S REALLY SWEET.
IT'S NOT TOO SPICY.
CHILI AND A BLACKBERRY.
THANKS.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD. IT WARMS
YOU UP FROM THE INSIDE OUT.
YOUR CONEYS ARE UP.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
EVERYBODY KNOWS ABOUT IT.
TWO BACONS ARE UP.
(man) IT'S JUST GREAT
DOWN-HOME COOKING.
THEY DO IT
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY, YOU KNOW.
HAVE A NICE EVENING.
WHEN WE WALK IN,
THEY KNOW US BY NAME.
YOU'RE WELCOMED
NO MATTER WHAT.
DAN, YOUR FISH AND CHIPS
ARE UP.
THERE'S A LOT OF PLACES
IN NORTHERN MINNESOTA,
BUT NOT LIKE GORDY'S.
REALLY, I MEAN,
THIS IS AN INSTITUTION.
GORDY'S IS THE BEST.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS KIND OF THERAPEUTIC,
YOU KNOW, GORDY.
OH, YEAH,
IT'S GOOD FOR YOU.
IT'S A HAPPY TIME,
RIGHT,
WHEN WE DON'T SEE ANY RED
ON THE OUTSIDE.
RIGHT.
PERFECT, YEP.
SO HOW MANY PATTIES
DO YOU THINK WE'VE DONE SO FAR?
ABOUT 40, 50.
WE'RE NOT EVEN ONE-TENTH
OF THE WAY DONE.
NO.
NO, WE'RE NOT EVEN CLOSE.
AWESOME.
I'M GLAD WE COULD
SPEND THIS TIME TOGETHER.
NEXT STOP...
S.O.S. GOING OUT!
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CALIFORNIA...
GOOD S.O.S.
GOOD, VERY GOOD.
FOR A MILITARY TAKE...
PREPARE TO EAT!
ON COMFORT FOOD.
EAT!
SEMPER FI DINER.
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
WE'VE LEARNED ON TRIPLE "D"
IS THERE'S NO SIMPLE DEFINITION
OF WHAT A DINER IS.
I MEAN, IT COULD BE DEFINED
BY REGION, FACILITY, THEME
OR, IN THIS CASE, ATTITUDE.
HERE WE ARE IN FOUNTAIN VALLEY,
CALIFORNIA,
ABOUT A MILE EAST
OF HUNTINGTON BEACH,
WHERE A FORMER MARINE IS SERVING
IT UP SEMPER FI-STYLE.
THIS IS PAUL'S COFFEE SHOP.
HASH BROWNS ON THE S.O.S.
SEMPER FI
IS THE MARINE CORPS,
WHICH IS SHORT
FOR SEMPER FIDELIS.
SEMPER FIDELIS--ALWAYS FAITHFUL.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY
COMING UP.
THERE'S ALWAYS
A TON OF VETS IN HERE.
INCLUDING OWNER
AND FORMER MARINE...
FRENCH FRIES READY.
PHIL MARTINEZ.
TUNA MELT UP!
WE'RE HERE AT PAUL'S,
BUT WE'RE COOKING WITH PHIL.
(Phil) PAUL ACTUALLY STARTED
THE PLACE ABOUT 27 YEARS AGO.
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU HAD IT, PHIL?
ABOUT FIVE YEARS NOW.
OKAY, RAUL.
AND YOU SAID, "YEAH, MILITARY
COFFEE SHOP--THAT'S THE TICKET."
THAT'S THE TICKET.
THREE MINUTES
ON THIS KOBE BEEF.
MARINE CORPS, 26 YEARS.
MARINE CORPS.
ARE YOU IN THE MILITARY?
YES, SIR, YEAH.
THANKS FOR SERVING.
NOW WHAT IF YOU'RE NOT A MARINE
OR IF YOU'RE NOT A SAILOR,
CAN YOU STILL COME IN?
OH, HECK, YEAH.
WELL, I'M A VETERAN
OF THIS PLACE.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
WELL SAID.
HE LOVES IT SO MUCH,
HE WROTE AND TOLD ME ABOUT IT.
TEN-FOUR
AND SO DID HE.
WHY DID YOU WRITE US?
FOR THE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
REALLY? IT'S THAT GOOD?
OH, IT'S THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
JUST ALL KINDS
OF REALLY GOOD FOOD.
PORK'S ALMOST UP.
THIS PORK STEAK
IS PHENOMENAL.
WHOSE RECIPE?
UH, IT'S MY RECIPE.
I'M GONNA PUT 'EM
IN THE PAN.
YOU LOOK
INSIDE OF HERE,
HOW IT'S ALL MARBLED
WITH THE FAT,
IT'S REALLY FORTIFIED
WITH FLAVOR.
OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE BIT
OF SEASONING SALT,
AND WE GOT SOME BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
THIS IS WHAT'S GONNA MAKE IT
OFF THE HOOK.
REALLY?
YEAH, SOME CINNAMON.
CINNAMON?! THAT SILLY LINE--
OFF THE HOOK.
CHOPPED ONIONS...
OKAY.
AND CILANTRO.
OKAY,
THAT'S THE OTHER ONE--
CINNAMON AND CILANTRO.
RUB IT ALL DOWN,
TOSS 'EM AROUND,
MAKE SURE THEY GET
SOME OF THAT GOOD FLAVOR.
I CAN SMELL THE CINNAMON
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
IT'S ALMOST
LIKE A DRY RUB, OKAY.
LIKE A DRY RUB, YEAH.
SO WE WRAP THESE UP,
THROW 'EM IN THE WALK-IN.
HOW LONG WILL WE
LET THESE MARINATE?
OVERNIGHT.
LET'S GET THAT PORK STEAK GOING.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND THIS IS GONNA GO
ON THE GRILL.
IT'S BASICALLY A PORK CHOP
ON STEROIDS.
IT'S CALLED A BLADE STEAK,
CUT FROM THE SHOULDER.
KICKER--CINNAMON,
AND I CAN SMELL THE CINNAMON
RIGHT NOW.
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE OIL
ON HERE,
GIVE IT A LITTLE COLOR
WHEN WE FLIP IT.
BAD BOY'S
ABOUT READY TO FLIP.
A LITTLE BIT OF JUICE
FLOATING AT THE TOP.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
THAT LOOKS LIKE A MANHOLE COVER
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
THIS THING'S READY.
YOU CAN PLATE IT UP.
AND WE'LL GET
OUR POTATOES.
A LITTLE HOME FRIES.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT ALL THAT JUICE
THAT JUST SITS RIGHT ON THERE
FROM THAT MARINADE.
CILANTRO AND CINNAMON.
MIGHT TAKE A LITTLE
GETTING USED TO,
LIKE ANOTHER COUPLE BITES,
BUT I THINK YOU GOT SOMETHING
HERE, DUDE.
THIS PORK REALLY IS CREAMY.
THESE FLAVORS--MMM--
COMPLEMENT IT.
IT ALMOST HAS
A MIDDLE EASTERN FLAVOR TO IT,
THAT KIND OF A KICK.
MY MOUTH WANTS APPLESAUCE
AS SOON AS IT
GETS THE CINNAMON KICK.
BUT HAVE SOME HOME FRIES
INSTEAD.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA FIND IT
ANYWHERE ELSE,
BUT I THINK
YOU'RE GONNA DIG IT.
(woman) PORK STEAK.
ALL THE DIFFERENT INGREDIENTS
THAT THEY COOK IT WITH
POP RIGHT OUT
EVERY TIME YOU EAT IT.
IT'S JUST OUTSTANDING.
I JUST LOVE THE PLACE.
THE FOOD WAS GREAT.
IT'S THAT CAMARADERIE
THAT'S IN HERE.
ONCE A MARINE,
ALWAYS A MARINE.
(Guy) THERE YOU GO.
(man)
THE MARINE CORPS ATMOSPHERE.
THE "SEMPER FI-NER DINER."
SERVIN' UP THIS
SEMPER FINER FAVORITE...
(woman) GET YOUR S.O.S.
S.O.S.
THAT DOESN'T STAND
FOR STEAK ON A SHINGLE.
NO, STUFF ON A SHINGLE.
IT'S SERVED MILITARY-STYLE
ON THE TRAY.
NO.
YEAH.
I WANT ONE OF THESE.
SOME OF OUR VETERANS
THAT COME IN HERE,
I WILL TELL 'EM, "YOU'RE
A VETERAN, YOU KEEP THE TRAY.
"YOU BRING IT BACK
ON VETERANS' DAY.
BRING YOUR TRAY IN,
AND YOU GET A FREE S.O.S."
THAT'S AWESOME, DUDE.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN, BUDDY.
GROUND BEEF ON THE FLATTOP.
DIFFERENT BRANCHES OF
THE SERVICE MAKE THEIR S.O.S.
A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
BUT THIS IS LIKE TRADITIONAL,
THE WAY THE MARINE CORPS MAKES
IT, BECAUSE WE USE GROUND BEEF.
WE'RE GONNA COME OVER HERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA START OUR GRAVY.
SOME HEAT GOING ON HERE.
ARE YOU A BUTTER-TYPE GUY?
I EAT A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
WELL, THIS BATCH
CALLS FOR 1 POUND.
OH.
LET IT START MELTING.
YOU CAN HAVE THE GRAVY
IF YOU RAN HERE.
THE BUTTER MELTS DOWN.
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE
CHICKEN BASE,
SOME GRANULATED GARLIC.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR FLOUR.
SO EQUAL PARTS
FAT AND FLOUR.
WHISK THAT IN UNTIL WE GET
OUR RIGHT CONSISTENCY HERE
THAT I'M LOOKING FOR.
WHERE DID YOU LEARN
HOW TO COOK?
I LEARNED A LOT
FROM MY DAD,
AND THEN A LOT I PICKED UP
ON MY OWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE 2% MILK.
THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE DOING
A GREAT JOB, MAN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME SEASONING SALT,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA BRING THIS
TO A BOIL UNTIL IT GETS THICK.
SO ARE WE READY?
WE'RE READY.
AND NOW THE GROUND BEEF'S DONE,
AND IT GOES IN.
THAT'S THE "S" IN S.O.S.
SERVE IT UP.
OUR HASH BROWNS RIGHT THERE,
GOT OUR TOAST RIGHT HERE,
ONE PIECE OF FRUIT,
KEEP YOU REGULAR.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT OFF
WITH OUR S.O.S.
PREPARE TO EAT!
EAT!
THE TRAY
IS WHAT MAKES IT.
MMM, STICK-TO-YOUR-RIBS.
STICK-TO-YOUR-RIBS S.O.S.
IT DOES HAVE
A CREAMINESS TO IT.
SO YOU LIKE IT?
DUDE, I LIKE IT.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S OLD-SCHOOL.
IT'S TOASTED BREAD,
MAKING YOUR OWN GRAVY,
PUTTING SOME MEAT IN THERE,
HERE'S SOME POTATOES,
EAT IT AND ENJOY IT--
SEMPER FI DINER.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
(man) AND THE FLAVOR
COMES OFF THE BEEF
ONTO THE MILK AND FLOUR, AND IT
JUST KIND OF MELTS IT TOGETHER,
AND IT'S GREAT.
S.O.S. GOING OUT!
THAT'S GOOD S.O.S.
IT'S GOOD, VERY GOOD.
YOU COME HERE, IT'S FAMILY,
AND IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
(man) CHICKEN-FRIED'S UP.
JUST WHAT YOU'D EXPECT HERE...
THE POT ROAST
IS LIKE NONE OTHER.
AND SOME OF WHAT
YOU WOULDN'T...
I'VE GOT
A KOREAN BEEF.
YEP, KOREAN BARBECUE...
KIND OF AN ORIGINAL.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
AT PAUL'S COFFEE SHOP...
ALL RIGHT, JOHN,
THERE YOU GO.
IN FOUNTAIN VALLEY,
CALIFORNIA...
CHEESEBURGER UP.
OWNER AND FORMER MARINE
PHIL MARTINEZ...
TUNA MELT WITH FRIES UP!
IS DOING MESS HALL HIS WAY.
BECAUSE OF PHIL, WE HAVE
A GROUP OF FORMER MARINES,
AND WE MEET HERE
EVERY TUESDAY MORNING.
BUT MILITARY CHOW...
HERE WE GO.
WE GOT YOUR S.O.S.
IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
WE DO A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING
TO ACCOMMODATE THE ETHNIC
BACKGROUNDS IN THE COMMUNITY.
THEY SERVE RICE
AND SPAM AND EGGS
AND ALL THE GOOD
HAWAIIAN LOCAL FOOD.
CRYSTAL, LOCO MOCO UP,
TABLE THREE.
WHAT ELSE IS GOOD HERE?
KOREAN BARBECUE
IS VERY GOOD.
I'VE GOT
A KOREAN BEEF.
IT'S AS GOOD AS ANYPLACE I'VE
HAD AT A KOREAN RESTAURANT.
REALLY?
AND THE KIMCHI
IS DARN GOOD.
WHAT DO WE HAVE
TO DO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR KOREAN BEEF.
ALSO KNOWN AS BULGOGI.
SURE.
OH, MY MOUTH'S
ALREADY STARTING TO WATER.
WE'VE GOT
SOME SLICED RIB EYE.
SUPER THINLY SLICED.
IT COMES EXACTLY THAT WAY
WHEN WE GET IT.
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
ONE OF MY WAITRESSES,
SUSIE.
ACTUALLY,
HER MOTHER'S RECIPE.
SO YOU'RE SEPARATING IT.
ONE OF THE KEYS HERE
IS WHEN YOU MAKE THIS MARINADE
IS THAT IT GETS
ON BOTH LAYERS OF THE MEAT
AND NOT JUST
ON ONE SIDE.
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME SESAME OIL,
COOKING SAKE.
OKAY, THEN WE GOT
OUR CHOPPED GARLIC.
NOW WHAT'S NEXT?
UH, THE ASIAN PEAR.
THAT'S A PEAR.
WHOO.
PEEL THE PEAR.
WE'RE AT PAUL'S, AND PHIL'S
GONNA PEEL THE PEAR.
SO YOU TAKE
SOME OF THE SKIN OFF.
WE'RE GONNA GRATE IT.
IT REALLY
MINCES IT DOWN.
IT REALLY DOES.
YOU GOT HALF
THAT ASIAN PEAR DONE.
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS
BEING ADDED INTO IT.
MINCED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, MINCED ONIONS
AND SUGAR.
(whistles)
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT
A LITTLE BIT MORE SWEET.
BROWN SOY SAUCE,
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS ALL UP.
NOW HOW LONG WILL YOU
LET THAT MARINADE?
OVERNIGHT.
SO COVER IT UP, LEAVE IT
IN THE WALK-IN 24 HOURS,
AND THEN, UH,
WE'RE GOOD TO COOK?
GOOD TO COOK.
A LITTLE BIT
OF COOKING OIL.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT IN A SKILLET,
AND WE'RE GONNA BROWN IT UP.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE IT
WITH TRADITIONAL
JAPANESE STICKY RICE
AND A HOMEMADE KIMCHI.
DIG IT.
SO IT'S NOT GROUND BEEF,
REMEMBER.
THIS IS SUPER SLICED RIB EYE.
MMM, REMIND YOU
A LOT OF TERIYAKI MEAT,
A LITTLE BIT
ON THE SWEETER SIDE.
MMM, IT'S ALL NATURAL.
IT'S MADE HERE.
IT'S ALL NATURAL.
THE MEAT
IS MEGA, SUPER TENDER.
KOREAN PICKLE.
HOMEMADE.
OH, YEAH,
THERE'S A LITTLE HEAT.
YOU'VE MADE IT RIGHT, TONS OF
FLAVOR. MMM. WELL, THANKS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
IT'S JUST REALLY SWEET,
AND IT PAIRS REALLY WELL
WITH THE KIMCHI, TOO.
YOU NEVER LEAVE HERE HUNGRY,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
YOU GOTTA BE THRILLED THAT THIS
IS WHAT YOU'RE SERVING PEOPLE.
I'M JUST GLAD
THEY'RE THRILLED.
HE'S A GREAT GUY.
HE HAS GREAT FOOD.
HE GIVES US A PLACE TO EAT,
AND IT'S TERRIFIC.
SUSIE, S.O.S. IS UP!
HE SERVES GREAT FOOD
FOR GREAT PEOPLE.
LISTEN, THANKS
FOR SERVING OUR COUNTRY,
AND THANKS
FOR SERVING OUR COUNTRY.
THANK YOU.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I GOT SOMETHING FOR YOU.
"HONORABLE GUY FIERI
IS COMMISSIONED
TO KENTUCKY COLONEL."
I'M TELLING YA, I GOTTA
CALL MY WIFE RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE TAKING DOWN
THE FAMILY PORTRAIT.