HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
USE MY SAMURAI SWORD.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I THINK THERE'S A PIRATE
THAT'S LOOKING FOR THIS.
SURF...
(man) GOT 45 POUNDS
THERE, BUB.
AND TURF...
RIB EYE STEAK
IN THE WINDOW.
NEAR JACKSONVILLE...
CRAB LEGS!
THE SEAFOOD SHACK...
FRIED SHRIMP.
BRINGING IT IN FRESH...
EVERYTHING I'VE EVER HAD
HERE IS WONDERFUL.
RIGHT OFF THE BOAT.
WHATEVER'S FRESH,
WE GOT IT.
AND IT'S ALL GOOD.
IN MANHATTAN BEACH,
CALIFORNIA...
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HE KNOWS WHAT HE'S DOING.
THE JOINT BY THE SURF...
BREAKFAST, LUNCH, DINNER--
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
CRANKIN' OUT...
CARBONARA ON FIVE!
ITALIAN FAVORITES.
THIS IS A CHEESE
EXPLOSION RIGHT HERE.
AND IN RENO...
LEMONADE PORK CHOPS!
STEAKS AND CHOPS...
PORKY DELICIOUSNESS.
FROM A SELF-TAUGHT CHEF...
TRI-TIP SANDWICH
WITH FRENCH FRIES!
WHO'S BREAKIN' THE RULES.
KETCHUP,
GRAPE JELLY.
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP
RIGHT HERE
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM OFF THE COAST
OF JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA,
IN MAYPORT, ONE
OF THE OLDEST FISHING VILLAGES
IN THE UNITED STATES.
NOW WHAT AM I LOOKING FOR?
EXACTLY--FRESH SEAFOOD.
NOW HOW FRESH? WELL,
I AM ON A SHRIMPIN' BOAT.
AND PART OF THE CATCH
FROM THIS BOAT
IS GOING TO A PLACE THAT'S BEEN
SERVIN' UP FRESH SEAFOOD
FOR OVER 40 YEARS.
THIS IS
SINGLETON'S SEAFOOD SHACK.
WHEN YOU SEE THE BOATS OUT BACK,
YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE GETTING
REAL FRESH SEAFOOD.
WE'VE GOT FRIED SHRIMP.
ALWAYS GOOD, ALWAYS FRESH
RIGHT OFF THE BOAT.
AS SOON AS YOU
WALK IN,
THERE'S THIS WHOLE DISPLAY
OF FRESH FISH...
WHATEVER'S FRESH,
WE GOT IT.
AND IT'S ALL GOOD.
'CAUSE OWNER
DEAN SINGLETON...
GOT ANY GOOD TODAY?
IS MAKIN' SURE.
I APPRECIATE IT,
RANDY.
OKAY, SO WHAT DO WE
GOT HERE?
(Dean)
FRESH FLOUNDER.
OKAY, HERE?
GROUPER.
THERE'S GONNA BE A TEST
AFTER THIS.
MAHI MAHI.
TRIGGERFISH.
FROM HERE?
FROM HERE.
THEY'VE ALWAYS GOT
A DIFFERENT SELECTION OF FISH
THAT WE'VE
NEVER HEARD OF.
WHAT'S THIS?
THAT'S A SHEEPSHEAD.
YEP, ANOTHER LOCAL CATCH,
SERVED UP WITH THEIR
OWN BLACKENING SPICE.
MMM. IT'S ABSOLUTELY
DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN' NOW?
RIGHT NOW WE'RE MAKING
THE BLACKENING SEASONING.
WHAT'S THE FIRST THING
GOIN' IN?
SEASONING SALT.
AND A MESS OF IT.
BLACK PEPPER.
OKAY.
OREGANO.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLD BAY.
A LITTLE
GRANULATED GARLIC.
JUST CHECKIN'.
JUST TRYIN'--
YEP.
'CAUSE I'M MAKIN'
A MENTAL NOTE OF THIS.
(speaking indistinctly)
START MY OWN PLACE DOWN THERE
CALLED DOUBLETON'S.
DOUBLETON'S?
THEN WE GOT PAPRIKA.
WE PUT DOUBLE PAPRIKA
AT DOUBLETON'S.
A LITTLE BIT OF...
CAYENNE. THAT'S NOT
A LITTLE BIT OF CAYENNE.
THAT'S GONNA BE--OKAY,
MIX IT UP, AND LET'S GO.
NICE TO JUST GO SHOPPING
IN YOUR OWN FRONT COUNTER.
WE JUST WALK RIGHT OVER
AND PICK IT UP.
YESTERDAY
IT WAS SWIMMIN'.
TODAY, NOT SO MUCH.
HE AIN'T SWIMMIN'.
USE MY SAMURAI SWORD.
I THINK THERE'S A PIRATE
THAT'S LOOKING FOR THIS.
AND DOES ONE WHOLE FILLET
COME FOR AN ORDER?
DEPENDING ON THE WEIGHT
AND SIZE.
OF THE PERSON
ORDERING IT?
(laughing)
THE NEW YORK STEAK
OF FISH.
IT'S PRIME RIB.
THAT'S THE PRIME RIB
OF FISH?
THAT'S IT.
OH, I GOTTA TRY THIS.
A LITTLE BLACKENING SEASONING--
YOU LIKE IT SPICY?
OH, YEAH.
RIGHT ONTO THE GRILL.
RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
THERE WE GO, AND...
(whistles)
YOU LIKE IT SPICY.
WOW.
(whispering) INHALE.
LET IT COOK FOR TWO,
THREE MINUTES--NOT LONG.
FLIP IT OVER AND--
FLIP IT OVER.
FOR ABOUT ONE
OR TWO MINUTES.
IS SHE READY TO GO?
SHE'S READY TO GO.
THERE YOU GO.
THE SHEEPSHEAD...
SHEEPSHEAD.
BLACKENED. MMM.
THAT'S GREAT. THAT'S A REALLY
FIRM BUT MOIST FISH.
LOOK AT THAT--PERFECT
FOR BLACKENING.
THAT WOULD BE MY EXAMPLE
OF WHAT I'D WANT BLACKENED FISH
TO TASTE LIKE--FRESH,
SIMPLE BLACKENING SPICE.
AND GOOD GREENS--THOSE ARE SUPER
TENDER. I'D SAY IT ALL WORKS.
NICE JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
YOU GOT THAT SHEEPSHEAD
DINNER COMIN'?
(man) COMIN' DOWN.
EVERYTHING I'VE EVER HAD
HERE IS WONDERFUL.
SHRIMP BURGER.
WE ENJOY EATING GOOD FISH
AND GOOD SHELLFISH.
FRIED SHRIMP.
MAYPORT AND SINGLETON'S
ARE BOTH FAMOUS
FOR THEIR SHRIMP.
FRIED SHRIMP,
SHRIMP SCAMPI,
FRIED SHRIMP SANDWICHES,
SHRIMP TACOS.
YOU'RE STARTING TO SOUND
A LITTLE LIKE BUBBA GUMP.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
AND BUBBA'S EVEN GOT
A BURGER.
SHRIMP BURGERS
GOIN' DOWN.
IT'S INCREDIBLY
FLAVORFUL.
FRIED PERFECTLY--
CRUNCHY ON THE OUTSIDE
AND VERY MOIST AND DELICIOUS
ON THE INSIDE.
AND DEAN'S NOT THE FIRST
GENERATION OF SINGLETONS
TO BRING IN THE CATCH
STRAIGHT FROM THE BOAT.
(man) WE'VE GOT
45 POUNDS THERE, BUB.
HIS DAD, RAY, WAS
A COMMERCIAL SHRIMPER
WHO STARTED THIS PLACE
BACK IN THE '60s.
JILL, CRAB LEGS!
AND THIS FAMILY TRADITION
GOES BACK EVEN FURTHER.
A COUPLE MENORCAN
CHOWDERS, PLEASE.
MENORCAN, MIYORCAN?
MENORCAN.
MENORCAN CHOWDER.
THERE'S A LITTLE ISLAND
OFF SPAIN CALLED MENORCA.
THAT'S WHERE MY HERITAGE
IS FROM.
RED CHOWDER.
(man) WELL, YOU CAN'T
GET IT EVERYWHERE.
IT'S GOT A UNIQUE TASTE.
IT'S LOADED WITH CLAMS.
AND WHERE ARE
THESE FROM?
FROM CEDAR KEY,
RIGHT AROUND TALLAHASSEE,
RIGHT AROUND THAT--
OKAY. THEY'RE FROZEN.
FROZEN. WE GET 'EM FRESH.
WE PUT 'EM IN THE FREEZER.
OKAY.
THE REASON WHY IS FOR ONE,
IT'S EASIER TO SHUCK.
TWO--IT SAVES
ALL THE SALTWATER,
AND ALL THE JUICES
STAY INSIDE OF IT.
OKAY, OKAY.
JUST TAKE IT
AND TAKE YOUR KNIFE.
(whistles)
GET THE CLAM OUT
ALL THE SALTWATER STAYS
RIGHT WITH IT.
SLAMMA-JAMMA,
THAT'S A BIG CLAM.
YES, SIR, WE CALL 'EM
CHOWDER CLAMS.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
ALL OF THESE OUT,
AND THEN WE'RE MAKING
MENORCAN CHOWDER
AFTER WE RUN IT
THROUGH THE BUFFALO CHOPPER.
EXACTLY.
THEY'RE STILL A LITTLE
PARTIALLY FROZEN,
SO THEY WON'T GUM UP. THEY'LL
JUST CUT INTO NICE PIECES.
YEP.
ALL RIGHT, BOSS.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA ADD
FRESH CHOPPED CLAMS.
A MESS OF 'EM.
I'M OUTTA HERE.
FRESH TOMATOES.
TOLD YOU IT WAS
GONNA SPLATTER.
SO WE'RE MAKING
MANHATTAN CLAM CHOWDER.
BASICALLY--
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
LET ME GUESS--
GRANULATED GARLIC.
YOU GOT IT.
GRANULATED GARLIC
CAPITAL OF THE WORLD.
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
CLAM BASE.
WOW.
WATER.
NOW HOW LONG
WILL THIS LAST?
UH, ABOUT A DAY,
MAYBE TWO.
REALLY?
YEAH. AND THEN WE PUT
BACON IN IT.
PRECOOKED BACON WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF ITS FAT.
YEP, LEAVE THE JUICE.
AND THEN WE STIR IT.
OKAY.
LET THE CLAMS COOK. LET IT
ALL KIND OF COME TOGETHER.
FOR 90 MINUTES,
THEN WE ADD ONIONS,
CELERY, BELL PEPPER.
CELERY AND BELL PEPPER?
YES.
I'M OVER HERE IN THE, UH,
SPLASH-FREE ZONE.
ADD POTATOES--LOOK OUT
FOR THE SPLASH, SON.
THERE YOU GO.
WE'LL STIR IT IN.
AND LET THAT GO
UNTIL IT HEATS BACK UP.
TILL IT GETS TO A BOIL.
WHAT ABOUT SALT AND PEPPER
AND ALL THAT KIND OF STUFF?
NO NEED.
NOT NECESSARY?
NOPE. THE CLAMS
HAVE IT.
THIS IS GONNA BE
INTERESTING.
THERE YOU GO.
LOOKS LIKE
MANHATTAN CHOWDER.
MMM. OH, THAT'S GREAT.
REMINDS ME A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF THE SEAFOOD CIOPPINO
THAN IT DOES MANHATTAN CHOWDER--
A LITTLE SPICE, A LITTLE ACID
THERE FROM THE LEMON JUICE.
CLAM FLAVOR, YOU GOT
A GOOD BACON FLAVOR.
MMM. REALLY GOOD, MAN. NO WONDER
YOU GO THROUGH SO MUCH.
I CAN VERY EASILY PUT A BOWL
OF THIS DOWN A DAY. MMM.
SERIOUSLY, I'M GONNA
POLISH THIS THING.
AND MENORCAN
CLAM CHOWDER.
THE TEXTURE IS GREAT.
THE CLAMS ARE GOOD,
AND IT'S LOADED
WITH OTHER GOODIES.
(woman) IT'S GOT A LOT
OF FLAVOR IN IT.
BIG FLAVOR,
BUT IT'S LIGHT.
YEAH.
I LOVE THE FACT THAT THERE ARE
ACTUALLY CHUNKS OF CLAMS.
YOU CAN SEE THE SEAFOOD
IN IT. IT'S SO GOOD.
YOU CAN ALWAYS COUNT ON IT
BEING JUST WHAT YOU WANT.
IT'S JUST GOOD FOOD.
AND CLAMS FOR EVERYONE.
A NICE PLACE TO COME
AND RELAX AFTER WORK.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
SINGLETON'S IS
REALLY SPECIAL TO US.
HUSH PUPPIES.
ALL RIGHT.
I JUST LOVE IT HERE.
I REALLY DO.
WHAT WOULD YOUR POPS THINK
OF ALL THIS GOING ON?
HE'D LOVE IT.
I WISH HE WAS HERE TO SEE,
YOU KNOW, HOW GOOD WE'RE DOIN'.
HE'S GOTTA BE SMILING
DOWN AT THIS.
DEFINITELY,
DEFINITELY, YEAH.
THAT'S AWESOME.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO CALIFORNIA...
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
FOR THAT OLD BEACHSIDE
FAVORITE...
CARBONARA ON SIX,
PLEASE!
KILLER LINGUINE.
THE PASTA
IS PHENOMENAL.
SO HERE WE ARE
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
AT ONE OF MY FAVORITE BEACHES--
MANHATTAN BEACH.
THIS PLACE IS FULL
OF CHARACTER.
AND SPEAKING OF CHARACTERS,
WE'RE AT A JOINT
WERE A DUDE BOUGHT
A ONE-WAY TICKET TO ITALY
TO FOLLOW HIS CULINARY PASSION.
THEN HE CAME HOME AND STARTED
COOKING UP THE REAL-DEAL FOOD
HERE AT THE BEACH.
THIS IS NORTH END CAFFE.
CARBONARA ON SIX,
PLEASE!
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
ONE NOTCH ABOVE
EVERYBODY ELSE'S.
THROW OUT
THE PASTA.
THE PASTA IS HOMEMADE. MMM.
I GOT A FUEGO ON 25.
ALL THE SANDWICHES
ARE JUST AMAZING.
(woman)
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HE KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOING.
'CAUSE JOHN ATKINSON'S BEEN
AT IT FOR MORE THAN 25 YEARS.
CUBANO ON 20!
BUT 8 YEARS AGO,
HE HIT A WALL.
I QUIT THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS FOR A WHILE,
JUMP ON A PLANE TO ROME,
A ONE-WAY TICKET.
NO.
AND THAT WAS IT--
ITALY.
AND THAT'S HOW
IT STARTED?
THAT'S HOW IT STARTED.
WHEN HE CAME BACK,
HE OPENED HIS OWN JOINT
WITH HIS NEW
FAVORITE RECIPES.
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
THEY DO IT RIGHT.
(woman) THE LINGUINE
CARBONARA.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND HOMEMADE ALL THE WAY.
OKAY, PASTA TIME.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH A COUPLE CUPS OF FLOUR.
ADD SOME BEATEN EGG,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
TO THAT EGG,
AND WE'RE
JUST GONNA MIX IT UP.
THE THING ABOUT MAKING
FRESH STUFF
THERE'S A CERTAIN ELASTICITY
TO IT WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT.
A TRUE PASTA.
MM-HMM. AT THIS STAGE,
JUST KNEAD IT.
NOW IT'S GETTING
SOME PLASTIC WRAP.
LET IT REST UP.
TAKE ABOUT A HALF AN HOUR.
ABOUT 30 MINUTE
IN THE FRIDGE.
OKAY, SO WE UNWRAP IT.
JUST KIND OF MAKE IT
INTO A SNAKE.
OKAY, SO WE START
IT OUT AT ONE.
AND FEED IT.
SO I'M GONNA DUST THIS,
AND I'M GONNA FOLD IT BACK OVER.
LAYERING
YOURSELF, OKAY.
ALL RIGHT? AND I'M GONNA
KICK IT UP TO TWO.
YOU GOTTA KINDA
SLOWLY GO THROUGH IT
TO REALLY BUILD
THIS TEXTURE.
I-I TAKE IT
ALL THE WAY UP TO FIVE.
IT'S GETTING TO ABOUT
LINGUINE LENGTH.
SQUARE IT OFF?
YOU GOTTA SQUARE
IT OFF.
SWITCHING GEARS OVER HERE.
GONNA GO TO THE CUTTING SIDE.
JUST FEED IT RIGHT DOWN
INTO YOUR HAND.
DIG IT.
NOW WE'RE CUTTING
THE PANCETTA.
WOW, TALK ABOUT GREAT FLAVOR,
GOOD SALT TO IT.
GOOD SALT.
MMM. DIG IT.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE MAKING THE SAUCE
FOR THE LINGUINE CARBONARA.
(John) WE'RE GONNA START WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL...
OKAY.
SOME PANCETTA--WE'RE GONNA
SEAR THIS UP NICE AND CRISP.
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT OF WINE.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM--
WE'RE READY FOR THE PASTA.
THAT'S A HEALTHY PORTION.
SO THAT'LL COME UP QUICK,
BEING THAT IT'S
FRESH PASTA.
ABOUT 30, 40 SECONDS.
GOING DIRECTLY
INTO THE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD BLACK PEPPER,
GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE TOSS.
NOW WE'RE DOING
A LITTLE EGG WHITE.
OFF THE HEAT REAL FAST.
HIT IT WITH SOME
PECORINO-ROMANO--
BETTER THAN PARMESAN.
THIS IS A ROMAN DISH...
OH, YEAH.
AND THAT'S A ROMAN CHEESE.
NOW TO FINISH IT,
DROP THE SUN RIGHT ON TOP.
(gasps) PASTA DISH--
GUY'S GONNA EAT IT WITH THE EGG.
THIS IS WHAT MAKES
THE SAUCE.
CARBONARA--EGG YOLK
IS WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
MMM. THE PASTA
IS PHENOMENAL.
MMM, PANCETTA'S GOT NICE CRISP
TO IT, NICE AND SALTY.
BUT THE KICKER TO THE WHOLE
THING--FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
AND THEN THE ONLY WAY TO DO IT
IS WITH THE PECORINO-ROMANO.
NICE JOB.
THANKS, DUDE.
CARBONARA ON FIVE!
I LOVE THE TEXTURE
OF THE PASTA.
THIS IS, UH,
A CHEESE EXPLOSION RIGHT HERE.
(John)
VEAL PICCATA IS READY!
JOHN HAS A WAY OF JUST COMBINING
THE PERFECT INGREDIENTS.
YOU KEEP IT FRESH. YOU KEEP
IT REAL--IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
AND IN THIS PLACE,
KEEPIN' IT REAL
IS A FAMILY TRADITION.
I NEED FRESH MOZZ!
DAD AND I DECIDED
TO DO THIS THING,
OUR BUILDING,
GRANDPA BOUGHT IT IN THE '50S.
YOUR FAMILY OWNS
THE BUILDING?
YES.
TWENTY FEET FROM THE BEACH?
ABOUT 40.
WHAT A CORNER SPOT
OF REAL ESTATE, BABY.
IT'S NOT BAD, MAN.
IT'S NOT BAD.
NO, IT'S NOT BAD.
WE'RE ABLE TO SORT OF
DO OUR OWN THING.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA LIVE
IN THE TRUE ITALIAN STYLE,
WHICH IS YOU BUY WHAT YOU NEED
TODAY, YOU USE IT TODAY,
AND THEN YOU ROLL.
YEAH, WE'RE DOIN' IT FRESH.
IF WE DON'T USE IT,
IT'S GONE.
I DIG IT.
AND JOHN'S BRINGING
HIS CULINARY PASSION
TO ALL KINDS
OF COOKING.
SOUTHERN-STYLE PORK RIBS!
COME AND GET 'EM!
HE HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
LIKE HIS TAKE
ON FUSION.
IT'S A MONTE CRISTO EGG ROLL
WITH KALUA PORK.
OKAY.
WE ARE DOING THE KALUA PIG
MONTE CRISTO EGG ROLLS.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE PUTTING IN
SOME BANANA LEAF.
YEAH. NOW WE GOT
A PORK BUTT.
NOW WE GOT ONE OF MY
SECRET INGREDIENTS.
THIS IS A SMOKED SALT
FROM MY BUDDY'S LITTLE MINE
IN MISSISSIPPI.
YOUR BUDDY HAS A
LITTLE MIME, HUH?
HE DOESN'T TALK
MUCH, BUT, UH...
RUB THIS GUY DOWN
WITH SALT.
OKAY.
WRAP IT UP TIGHT
IN QUITE A BIT OF BANANA LEAF.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
SO WE DON'T BURN
ON THE BOTTOM OF THAT PAN.
ON THE BOTTOM.
IN THE OVEN?
INTO THE OVEN--
220, 12 HOURS.
FANTASTIC.
WE ARE NOW MAKING
THE WASABI MOJO
FOR THE KALUA PIG.
WE'VE GOT SOME MAYONNAISE,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE TERIYAKI,
WASABI POWDER,
A LITTLE BIT OF HONEY,
SESAME OIL,
A LITTLE FRESH GINGER.
OKAY.
GIVE IT A STIR.
LET IT SET UP.
LET SOME OF THAT WASABI
WORK IT'S WAY THROUGH THE MAYO.
AND THEN WE'RE
GOOD TO GO.
NOW WE'RE PULLING OUT
THE KALUA PIG.
LET IT COOL DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW MUCH
MOISTURE IS LEFT IN THERE.
YOU KNOW,
I DON'T OFTEN DO THIS,
BUT I'M JUST GONNA SAMPLE
SOME OF THIS.
MMM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
MEGA-SUPER-OUT OF BOUNDS-
SUPERCALIFRAGILISTIC TENDER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LET'S PROCEED.
MM-HMM.
SO NOW I'M GONNA START
JUST BREAKING IT UP.
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS
COOKING LIQUID.
THIS IS READY TO GO. AND WE'RE
GONNA ASSEMBLE THE EGG ROLL.
START WITH A PIECE
OF SWISS CHEESE,
A SLICE OF BLACK FOREST HAM,
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR KALUA PIG.
I LIKE IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SCALLION.
THIS IS OUR TERIYAKI.
OKAY.
A LITTLE SESAME SEED.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF EGG WASH
TO SEAL IT.
CORNER TO CORNER,
WRAP IT OVER.
AND THEN TUCK
THOSE ENDS IN.
YEAH, NICE, DUDE.
OH, YEAH, YOU'RE
TALKING TO A DUDE
THAT MAKES A LOT
OF EGG ROLLS.
WE GOT OUR WASABI MOJO
AND OUR TERIYAKI SAUCE.
THERE YOU GO. GET DOWN.
MMM. TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT.
THE KALUA PIG JUST REALLY
ROCKS AND ROLLS. MMM.
GREEN ONION,
THE HAM, CHEESE,
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE, UH...
WASABI MOJO.
I JUST WANT TO HEAR
YOU SAY, "MONEY."
THAT'S LIKE BANK.
BANK?
I MEAN, THERE'S MONEY,
AND THEN THERE'S BANK.
KALUA PORK EGG ROLL.
THE SAUCE COMPLEMENTS THE PORK--
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH, DELICIOUS.
THIS PLACE
IS AWESOME.
AND YOU ARE HAVING
THE FUEGO BURGER.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH, DINNER--
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH
AND DINNER.
IT'S CALLED MOVING IN,
I THINK.
I GOT FRIES
ON THIS, PLEASE!
YOU TOTALLY COMMIT
YOURSELF.
DUDE, YOU DESERVE IT.
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN.
YEAH, MAN.
NEXT STOP...
LEMONADE PORK CHOPS!
WE'RE HEADING TO RENO...
MM-HMM,
THAT'S FLAVOR CITY
RIGHT THERE.
TO GO ALL-IN.
SO HERE I AM--
RENO, NEVADA,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S BEEN OPEN SINCE 1956.
AND GET THIS--THESE FOLKS
HAVE ONLY CLOSED THE DOOR
FOR ONE DAY IN ALL THAT TIME.
THEY HAVE BEEN ROCKIN'
AND ROLLIN' OLD-SCHOOL STYLE
24-7 FOR OVER 54 YEARS
OR 473,000 HOURS.
THIS IS GOLD 'N SILVER INN.
MEAT LOAF, EXTRA GRAVY!
(man) BEST GRAVY IN TOWN.
I LIKE
THE BREAD PUDDING.
MADE OUT OF DONUTS.
THIS IS THE LOCALS'
PLACE TO GO.
THIS IS IT.
(woman) I FEEL LIKE IT COULD
BE IN THE MID '70s...
HELLO.
WHICH I REALLY LIKE.
SERVIN' SLOTS ON ONE SIDE
AND STEAKS ON THE OTHER...
RIB EYE STEAK
IN THE WINDOW!
COOKED UP BY EXECUTIVE CHEF
LENNY CURTIS...
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
WHO'S CRANKIN' OUT
ALL THE CLASSICS...
B.L.T. SANDWICH
AND A CHICKEN FRIED STEAK
ON TABLE TEN.
AND A FEW RECIPES
OF HIS OWN.
ONE ORDER OF LEMONADE
PORK CHOPS, PLEASE!
JUST A GOLD 'N SILVER
FAVORITE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE LEMONADE
FOR THE BAKED LEMONADE
PORK CHOPS.
LEMON AND PORK--
I DIG IT.
BUT REALLY?
LEMONADE YOU MAKE?
YEAH, START
WITH WHOLE LEMONS,
THE RINDS, THE SEEDS
AND EVERYTHING.
THEN WE ADD SUGAR.
GRIND 'EM TO DEATH.
NOW WE ADD IN WHAT?
WATER. WE PROCESS 'EM UP,
THEN STRAIN THE PULP
AND THE JUICE OUT
TILL WE GET ABOUT
A GALLON OF LEMONADE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
LEMONADE MADE LIKE THAT.
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO TASTE IT?
(whistles)
YOU HAVE THE OIL
IN THE RIND...
RIGHT.
GETTING INTO THAT--THAT'S
WHY THAT TASTES SO RICH.
YOU GET THE BAM--
THE TRUE FLAVOR.
THAT'S CHANGED
MY LEMONADE ATTITUDE.
AND THIS IS ALL COMING
TOGETHER FOR WHAT?
OUR SAUCE FOR OUR
LEMONADE PORK CHOPS.
WE ADD THE KETCHUP,
AND WE ADD THE BROWN SUGAR,
3 NICE CUPS OF SOY SAUCE,
GIVE IT THAT GOOD SALTY FLAVOR.
VINEGAR?
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR, GIVE IT
THAT LITTLE BIT OF BITE.
THAT'S AN INTERESTING
CONCOCTION, MY FRIEND.
PAPRIKA--MAKE IT
NICE AND RED.
CHILI POWDER, GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER.
WHERE DID YOU FIRST
MAKE THIS RECIPE UP?
I TRY ALL MY RECIPES ON
MY CHILDREN AND MY WIFE FIRST.
ALL RIGHT.
THEN WE'RE DOING GINGER, BASIL.
AND YOU HAVE THYME--FRESH--
AND SOME FRESH OREGANO.
THEN YOU STIR IT UP.
NOW ADD THE PORK CHOPS? YOU'RE
GONNA BAKE IT IN THE SAUCE, HUH?
YOU'RE GONNA BAKE IN
IN THE SAUCE.
OKAY, LET'S DO
SOME PORK CHOPS.
OKAY.
YOU CUT
YOUR OWN CHOPS.
YES, I DO. CUT OUR OWN STEAKS
ALSO--EVERYTHING.
THIS IS WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
SLOW DOWN.
TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
I'VE DRIVEN
RIGHT BY THIS PLACE.
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ADDING OIL.
YOU CAN HEAR IT SIMMER.
AND WE START FLOURING
ONE PORK CHOP AT A TIME
TO SEASON.
A FRY FLOUR.
YEAH.
OKAY, SO JUST BROWN BOTH SIDES,
LET THAT BREADING HOOK UP.
EXACTLY.
OH, THAT'S
WHAT I'M HAVING.
ARE YOU READY?
DO IT, BROTHER.
HIT THE SAUCE.
RIGHT OVER THE TOP--
YOU WANT TO STIR IT UP BEFORE
AND IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE COOKING.
OKAY. AND IT IS
GOING TO REDUCE.
YES, IT IS.
GET IT IN THE OVEN.
OKAY. DOUBLE PLASTIC,
DOUBLE TIN FOIL--
350 FOR...
ABOUT I'D SAY AN HOUR
AND 45 MINUTES.
YOU READY?
DO IT, MAN.
SMELL THE AROMA.
THAT'S NUTS, MAN.
LOOK AT THE SAUCE, HOSS.
THERE YOU GO--
NICE AND JUICY.
GOT YOUR FORK READY?
MM-HMM.
DUDE, THAT'S FLAVOR CITY
RIGHT THERE.
YES.
IT REMINDS ME
OF SWEET-AND-SOUR SAUCE...
MM-HMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT,
A LITTLE BIT OF VINEGAR.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT BITE IN THERE.
SEE HOW THE SAUCE IS COOKED
ALL THE WAY DOWN INTO THE CHOP.
THIS IS THE OLD-SCHOOL STYLE
AND PROBABLY THE WAY YOUR
GRANDMA MADE 'EM,
BUT WITH A NEW ATTITUDE
AND SOME REALLY BIG FLAVOR.
COOL.
I HAVE THE LEMONADE
PORK CHOPS.
THE PORK CHOP
IS TO DIE FOR.
IT'S FALL-OFF-THE-ONE TENDER,
PORKY DELICIOUSNESS.
LEMONADE PORK CHOPS!
AND THEY ALWAYS HAVE
GREAT FOOD.
TRI-TIP SANDWICH.
WE LOVE THIS PLACE. WE CAME HERE
SINCE I WAS, LIKE, THIS BIG.
(man) I'VE ONLY BEEN
COMING HERE FOR 50 YEARS.
OH, JUST 50?
JUST A ROUND NUMBER?
ENJOY.
(both) THANK YOU.
THIS IS AN INSTITUTION.
IT IS.
THAT OWNER JEFF PAINE...
HOW ARE YOU?
HAS BEEN RUNNING
SINCE 1989.
HOW YOU FOLKS DOIN'?
AND IT'S REALLY TURNED
INTO KIND OF A 3-
OR 4-GENERATION BUSINESS NOW.
THAT'S STILL CRANKIN' OUT
THIRD AND FOURTH
GENERATION FAVORITES...
MEDIUM-RARE!
LIKE--GET THIS...
GROUND BEEF POUNDER.
A 1-POUND HAMBURGER SMOTHERED
IN HOMEMADE GRAVY.
A VEAL GRAVY.
YES.
VEAL BONES?
YES, VEAL SHANKS. ROAST 'EM OFF
IN THE OVEN AT 350 DEGREES
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF
TO TWO HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE FLAVOR IS
FROM THAT MARROW.
HOW DO WE PUT IT
TOGETHER?
FIRST YOU PUT
THE MIREPOIX IN.
CARROTS, CELERY AND ONIONS.
TOMATO JUICE?
RIGHT.
THEN YOU PUT THE ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER,
A LITTLE BIT
OF WHITE PEPPER, SALT.
THE SALT.
BRAISED VEAL BONES IN.
IS THAT BLOND HAIR I SEE?
YOU GUYS SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON RIGHT HERE?
WHAT COLOR IS YOUR HAIR
NATURALLY?
WHAT'S YOURS NATURALLY?
WHO KNOWS? I HAVEN'T
SEEN IT IN A WHILE.
UH-HUH.
SCRAPE THE BONE MARROW
OFF OF THE PAN.
THAT'S WHAT REALLY MAKES
A GOOD STOCK GRAVY.
DIG IT.
FILL HER UP WITH WATER?
TILL WE'VE GOT ABOUT
3 TO 4 GALLONS.
THEN WE ADD THE TOMATOES.
ABOUT HOW LONG
DO WE LET IT SIMMER?
48 HOURS.
REALLY?
YEAH. IT COOKS
FOR TWO DAYS.
WOW.
THEN WE'LL STRAIN IT...
RIGHT.
AND THEN GET INTO
MAKING THE GRAVY.
YEP. TAKE
THE CARAMEL COLOR.
NICE BLOND ROUX.
WORK IT IN REAL GOOD.
LET IT CONTINUE
TO COOK.
FOR A GOOD 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR.
AND THIS GOES ON THAT
BIG 1-POUND PATTY, TOO?
GOES ON THE BIG POUNDER.
START IT OFF ON THE GRILL
TO SEAR THE MEAT.
IT KEEPS IN THE FLAVOR.
80-20?
YEAH, BUT IT'S
ANGUS GROUND CHUCK.
ABOUT AS GOOD
AS YOU CAN DO.
OKAY, SO YOU PUT
A LITTLE MARK ON IT.
YEP.
OH, THIS IS LOOKING GOOD.
YOU READY?
YEAH.
A 1-POUND
GROUND BEEF STEAK.
LOOK AT THAT.
RIGHT ON THERE.
OH, HO.
A LITTLE CARAMELIZED
GRILLED ONION.
GRAVY ON THE PATTY--
THIS IS ABOUT AS OLD-SCHOOL
AS IT GETS RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS EVEN
BEFORE MY TIME.
MMM. THE GRAVY'S OUTSTANDING--
REAL FLAVOR.
48 HOURS--
YOU CAN TASTE IT.
LITTLE THINGS JUST LIKE
GETTING IT FROM SCRATCH,
HAVING THE GRILLED ONIONS--
HE'S DOING THE FOOD RIGHT.
I LIKE THAT.
THE GROUND BEEF POUNDER.
THE GRAVY'S RICH AND BEEFY.
KIND OF LIKE SALISBURY STEAK
BUT MORE HEARTY.
GROUND BEEF POUNDER!
(man) JUST FALLS IN LINE
WITH EVERYTHING ELSE.
IT'S JUST GOOD FOOD.
LIKE THIS WEST COAST CLASSIC.
TRI-TIP SANDWICH
WITH FRENCH FRIES!
DONE WITH A TWIST...
(Guy) KETCHUP,
GRAPE JELLY.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WOW.
AT GOLD 'N SILVER INN
IN RENO, NEVADA...
EVERYTHING WAS GOOD?
OWNER JEFF PAINE...
THANKS FOR COMIN' IN.
AND EXECUTIVE CHEF
LENNY CURTIS...
MEAT LOAF,
EXTRA GRAVY!
ARE SERVIN' IT UP OLD-SCHOOL,
LIKE THIS WESTERN FAVORITE.
TRI-TIP SANDWICH
IN THE WINDOW!
WITH A SAUCE MADE FROM--
GET THIS--
GRAPE JELLY AND PEPPER
AND KETCHUP.
AND IT ALL STARTS
WITH 10 POUNDS OF TRI-TIP.
WE HAVE TO TRIM
THE TRI-TIP.
THAT'S A GREAT PIECE OF MEAT.
IT'S REAL BIG IN CALIFORNIA.
OKAY, IT'S ALL TRIMMED UP.
WHAT DO WE GOT GOING NOW?
SOME MARINADE FOR OUR
TRI-TIP SANDWICH--
HOMEMADE BARBECUE SAUCE.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
BARBECUE SAUCE.
YES, WE DO.
WHAT DON'T THEY MAKE
IS THE QUESTION.
THEN THE BEER, THEN WE PUT
ABOUT 2 CUPS OF WATER.
THIN IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
CRACKED PEPPERCORNS. THEN I'M
GONNA STIR IT UP REAL GOOD.
GET THIS ALL TOGETHER, THEN YOU
JUST POUR THIS STUFF IN.
TO THE TOP.
PUT IT IN YOUR REFRIGERATOR
AND LET IT SET.
OKAY. SO WHERE
ARE WE AT?
TAKE THE TRI-TIP,
START IT OFF ON THE GRILL.
WE MARK IT REAL GOOD.
BOTH SIDES,
AND THEN WE'LL
TAKE IT OFF.
THROW 'EM IN THE OVEN
A LITTLE BIT,
GET 'EM
TO A MEDIUM RARE.
OKAY, NOW WHAT
ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING A, UH,
HOMEMADE SAUCE
CALLED A MAHOGANY SAUCE.
I GOTTA SEE
THE GRAPE JELLY THING.
FIRST THING WE DO
IS ADD BUTTER, ONIONS.
THEN YOU ADD THE BACON.
WE'LL NEED THAT FAT
IN THE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE THE FAT
IN THE SAUCE SO IT STICKS
TO YOUR RIBS.
WE ADD THE KETCHUP.
THEN YOU ADD
THE GRAPE JELLY.
KETCHUP, GRAPE JELLY.
YES.
THAT JUST DOESN'T
LOOK RIGHT.
OH, IT'S WONDERFUL, DUDE.
LIQUID SMOKE.
GRAPE JELLY
AND LIQUID SMOKE.
NOW HOW LONG WILL WE
LET IT SIMMER?
ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
JUST LET IT REDUCE DOWN.
OKAY, SO WE'RE
COOKED DOWN HERE.
YOU'RE SURE THAT THIS ISN'T
PLAYING SOME GAME ON ME.
IT REMINDS ME
OF SWEDISH MEATBALL SAUCE.
I ACTUALLY USE IT
AT WEDDINGS ON MEATBALLS.
YEAH.
I WAS AT THAT WEDDING.
WHAT DO WE GOT GOING NOW?
TAKE THE TRI-TIP,
WE SLICE IT REAL THIN.
START IT ON THE FLATTOP,
THEN WE WANT TO ADD THE ONIONS.
YOU SEE WHERE THE MEAT STARTS
CARAMELIZING. WE TURN IT OVER.
AND THEN WE THROW IT
INTO OUR MAHOGANY SAUCE.
STIR IT UP IN THERE.
GET IT NICE AND SOAKING WET.
AND WE LAY IT OUT
ON THE SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THE COLOR ON THE--
THAT'S CRAZY.
SOME OF THOSE GOOD
CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
A MEAL MADE FOR A KING.
MMM. THAT IS
A GOOD SANDWICH.
THAT MAHOGANY SAUCE, THAT'S
WEIRD, BUT WEIRD GOOD.
YOU WANT TO GO,
"OH, IT'S BARBECUE SAUCE.
NO, NO, NO, IT'S
SWEET-AND-SOUR SAUCE--NO, NO."
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT SAUCE IT IS.
THE TRI-TIP, BY THE WAY,
IS MEGA TENDER.
I LIKE THIS LITTLE THING YOU DO
WHERE YOU COME FROM THE--
FROM THE GRILL
TO THE FLATTOP,
AND YOU DID IT
WITH THE BURGER, TOO,
PUT A NICE LITTLE
CRUST ON IT.
IT'S INTENSE CARAMELIZATION
IS WHAT IT IS.
MMM. NICE JOB, MAN.
GOOD JOB.
RIGHT ON, BUDDY.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
IT'S VERY JUICY.
TRI-TIP SANDWICH
WITH FRENCH FRIES!
THE FLAVOR JUST EXPLODES
IN YOUR MOUTH.
(woman) IT IS SO GOOD.
OH, I HAD ONE.
IT'S NUTS.
TWO LEMONADE PORK CHOPS,
AND ONE FISH AND CHIPS!
THIS IS REALLY OLD-FASHIONED,
GOOD COOKING.
AND THEY'VE GOT EVERYTHING--
THE SLOT MACHINES OVER THERE.
24 HOURS.
I'VE SEEN JOINTS ALL ACROSS
THE COUNTRY. I WILL DEFINITELY
TELL YOU YOU'VE GOT ONE
OF THE UNIQUE ONES, SO...
THAT'S GREAT. WE'RE HAPPY
TO BE HERE. THANKS.
NICE TO MEET YOU, BROTHER.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
SO HERE I AM--RENO, NEVADA,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S BEEN OPEN SINCE 1956.
(chokes)
(laughter)