HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHAT?
FAST FOOD...
OKAY, YOUR CHILI DOG'S OUT.
THEIR WAY...
TWO PASTRAMI MOMMIES TO GO.
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA...
ORDER FOR JOSH.
L.A. STREET FOOD...
MMM.
YOU KNOW, TACOS...
ULTIMATE L.A. TACO.
AND CHINESE...
I HAVE A CHIMALE.
CHINESE TAMALE.
I LIKE IT, MAN.
IN HONOLULU...
MIX PLATE READY.
THE 48-YEAR-OLD DRIVE-IN...
SHOYU CHICKEN.
CRANKING OUT CLASSICS...
CHILI DOG PLATE.
HAWAIIAN-STYLE.
LOCO MOCO SUNNY-SIDE UP.
BROTHER, MAN,
THAT'S GREAT GRAVY.
THANK YOU.
AND IN MINNESOTA...
DeWITT SEITZER
WITH PORK LOIN.
THE LOCAL FAVORITE...
UNBELIEVABLE.
WHERE A FAST FOOD...
PASTRAMI MOMMY.
IS SMOKING.
LOOK AT THE COLOR.
HUMONGOUS FLAVOR.
YOU SHOULD START
DOING THIS PROFESSIONALLY.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN L.A.
LOOKING FOR A TACO TRUCK.
NOW NOT JUST ANY TACO TRUCK,
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
1 OF OVER 55 GOURMET FOOD TRUCKS
THAT ARE BLOWING UP
THE L.A. SCENE.
NOW, YOU CAN FIND
THE NEW LOCATION EVERY DAY.
THE ONLY TOUGH PART
IS SOMETIMES GETTING THERE.
BUT NO WORRIES, HERE WE ARE,
DON CHOW TACO TRUCK.
ORDER FOR JOSH,
THREE TACOS.
MMM.
AND NOT JUST ANY TACOS...
ONE CHINESE
BBQ PORK TACO.
WHO WOULD EXPECT
ASIAN AND MEXICAN FOOD
MIXED TOGETHER ON A TRUCK?
WELL, OWNERS LAWRENCE LIE...
SOY GINGER SHRIMP TACO.
AND DOMINIC LAU...
PLEASE ENJOY YOUR ORDER.
THAT'S WHO.
BORN AND RAISED IN L.A.
FROM CHINESE DESCENT.
IF YOU LIVE IN L.A. YOU CAN'T
HELP BUT HAVE GOOD MEXICAN FOOD.
WHY NOT PUT
THE TWO TOGETHER?
SO A LITTLE OVER A YEAR AGO,
THEY RENTED A TACO TRUCK
AND BROUGHT IN RESTAURANT VET
ERNIE GALLEGOS...
TOFU BURRITO.
TO DO THE COOKING.
MET UP WITH THESE PEOPLE,
AND HERE I AM.
MAKING DON CHOW'S CHINO LATINO
LIKE THIS FAVORITE...
BBQ CHINESE PORK TACO--
I HAVE DREAMS ABOUT IT.
IS THIS ONE OF THOSE
POPULAR ITEMS?
THIS IS THE MOST POPULAR.
START OFF WITH SOME OIL.
WE'RE ON SOME STREET HERE.
WE'RE ON A SLANT.
THE OIL'S RUNNING TO THE BACK
OF THE FLATTOP.
YEAH.
OKAY, SO PORK BUTT
GOES ON.
I'M GONNA DO
THE FAT SIDE DOWN.
SEAR IT WITH
SOME SEASONING SALT.
OKAY, PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON IT.
THEN WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
AND THEN WE'LL PUT IT
ON THE STOVETOP.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME OIL, THE SEARED PORK BUTT.
LET THE FAT RENDER DOWN.
IT COULD TAKE
ABOUT TWO HOURS TO COOK.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA CUBE IT.
EXACTLY.
NOW ARE YOU EVER PREPPING
WHILE HE'S DRIVING?
NEVER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
BACK THERE?
THAT'S MY BREAK TIME.
GET A "MISSION: IMPOSSIBLE"
HARNESS,
AND YOU COULD JUST FLOAT
AND COOK.
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING NEXT?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CHINESE BBQ SAUCE.
I'M GONNA START OFF WITH SOME
HOISIN, CHINESE RICE WINE,
SESAME OIL...
(whistles)
CHINESE DARK SOY SAUCE,
TAPATIO SAUCE.
'CAUSE IT HAS TO BE TAPATIO.
IT HAS TO BE MEXICAN HOT SAUCE.
DON'T.
THEY'RE--THEY'RE--
I-I-I--
CHINESE FIVE-SPICE,
GROUND GINGER.
I'M NOT TELLING YOU
ANY OF THE SURPRISES
THAT ARE AROUND THE CORNER.
AND A RABBIT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GRANULATED ONION.
GRANULATED ONION
AND HONEY.
THAT'S AN INTERESTING ONE.
AND JUST WHISK IT
ALL TOGETHER.
SO THIS IS DONE.
DO WE TASTE THIS?
MMM. SOMEBODY KNEW WHAT
THEY WERE DOING WITH THAT.
SO THIS IS READY.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA PREPARE
A TACO.
HE LOOKS LIKE
FATHER OF THE CULINARY TRUCK.
BLESS THIS MEAL.
ADD A LITTLE OIL TO THE GRILL.
GRILL THE PORK.
THEN WE'LL HIT SOME OF
THAT CHINESE GLAZE TO IT.
EXACTLY.
A COUPLE TORTILLAS.
SO YOU DOUBLE UP
THE TORTILLAS.
ABSOLUTELY.
NOW I WANT IT AS CRISPY AS
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE CRISPY...
YEP.
I'M GONNA TOP IT OFF
WITH SOME ONIONS AND CILANTRO,
A LITTLE MILD SALSA
AND A LIME WEDGE,
AND THERE'S OUR TACO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
FATHER TACO'S WATCHING.
IT'S ALL GOOD.
MMM. AMEN. NICE TACO.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEETNESS
OF THIS ASIAN BARBECUE SAUCE.
YOU GET THE GREAT PORK FLAVOR
COMING THROUGH,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICINESS
FROM THE TOMATILLO SALSA. MMM.
THE CILANTRO WORKS.
AND THE RAW ONION--ON POINT.
THE QUESTION IS, WHY HASN'T
THIS BEEN DONE BEFORE?
FATHER TACO'S ON PREMISE,
AND YOU GET YOURSELF BLESSED
WITH ONE OF THESE BAD BOYS.
WAY TO DO IT.
TWO CHINESE
BBQ PORK TACOS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
JUICY, LOVE THE MEAT.
CHINESE BBQ PORK TACO.
IT'S A MIX OF SPICY AND SWEET.
I'M TELLING YOU,
I REALLY AM OBSESSED WITH IT.
AND THE HIGHEST PRAISE YOU
COULD GET FROM THIS CROWD...
CHASE HER.
WE'RE GONNA CHASE IT DOWN.
IF YOU MISS 'EM, DO YOU KNOW
WHERE THEY'RE GOING NEXT?
(man) NOT NECESSARILY.
NO.
YOU GOT TO BE ON THE IN?
YOU TOTALLY DO.
WE FOLLOW THEM ON twitter.
IT'S LIKE A LITTLE BIT
OF A CULT FOLLOWING.
MOST TRUCKS HAVE BETWEEN 2,500
AND 50,000 twitter FOLLOWERS.
SEE, THEY'RE JUST RACING
UP HERE
TO GET SOME OF THE DON CHOW.
(man) CARNE ASADA TORTA.
PULL UP, YOU KNOW
YOU'RE GONNA GET GREAT FOOD?
ABSOLUTELY.
AND FRESH, TOO.
FROM THE L.A. TACO
WITH CITRUS MARINATED STEAK...
MMM.
THE BACON AND ONIONS ON TOP OF
IT, THAT MAKES IT THE ULTIMATE.
TO A SOY GINGER TOFU TACO.
HEAR THAT EVERY DAY,
DON'T YA?
MMM.
I HAVE A CHIMALE.
CHIMALE.
CHINESE TAMALE.
FILLED WITH KUNG PAO CHICKEN.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
♪ KUNG PAO CHICKEN BRINE ♪
COULD EVEN BE LIKE A SONG.
COULD BE A COUNTRY SONG.
YEAH, IT COULD BE.
(imitates guitar strum)
OKAY.
START OFF WITH SOME WATER,
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK,
SOME OF
OUR GROUND CHILI BASE,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT
AND SOME CANOLA OIL.
THAT'S THE KUNG PAO
CHICKEN BRINE?
THAT'S IT,
AN OLD CHINESE SECRET.
SO WE'LL BRING IT UP TO A BOIL.
WE'LL LET THE BRINE COOL.
THEN WE'LL ADD
THE DICED CHICKEN TO IT
AND LET IT MARINATE OVERNIGHT.
SO WE'RE READY NOW.
THAT'S IT.
IT'S GONNA GO INTO THE...
THE CHIMALES.
OKAY.
START OFF WITH A LITTLE OIL,
CANOLA OIL, ONIONS, TOMATO.
WE'LL LET THOSE BROWN UP
A LITTLE BIT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
WE'LL LET THAT SAUTé.
AND THEN WE'LL ADD
OUR BRINED CHICKEN BREAST.
OKAY.
CHICKEN BASE.
AND A LITTLE...
TOMATO SAUCE.
ROASTED CHILE de ARBOL.
A LITTLE CORNSTARCH SLURRY
TO TIGHTEN IT UP.
LET THIS COOK DOWN.
TAKE IT OFF THE HEAT.
RIGHT.
WHAT ARE WE ON, MAN?
MAKE SOME MASA
FOR THE CHIMALES.
START OFF MASECA.
THE BASE FOR THE TAMALES
OR THE CHIMALES.
THERE WE GO.
VEGETABLE SHORTENING.
BAKING POWDER,
A LITTLE SALT.
MIX THIS.
I LIKE TO MIX IT, MIX IT.
THEN WE'LL ADD
OUR WATER TO IT.
AND THIS IS THE CONSISTENCY
THAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR,
KIND OF A STICKY--
BUT NOT WET.
EXACTLY.
PICK THE RIGHT HUSKS.
PLACE THAT IN THE CENTER.
OKAY.
BACK OF THE SPOON,
NICE THIN LAYER.
AND THEN WE'LL TAKE
OUR CHILLED FILLING.
ROLL IT OVER.
ROLL IT UP.
A LITTLE WAX PAPER TO KEEP 'EM
ALL TOGETHER INSIDE OF IT
AND STEAM 'EM AWAY.
WE DO ABOUT
AN HOUR AND 15 MINUTES.
ARE THEY READY?
FINISHED PRODUCT.
THOSE LOOK GREAT.
TAKE ONE OVER HERE
TO THE TABLE.
LET'S GO, BABY.
THEN WE'LL TOP IT WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF OUR PICO de GALLO.
SO A CHIMALE,
A CHINESE TAMALE.
IT'S KILLING YOU, ISN'T IT?
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD TAMALE.
AND A TAMALE YOU GUYS MADE.
THE MASA.
I LIKE IT, MAN.
I MEAN, IT'S TENDER,
GOT A LITTLE SALT.
THE CHICKEN'S GOT GOOD SPICE
AND GOOD FLAVOR.
THE PICO de GALLO IS ON POINT.
I'D LINE UP EVERY DAY
TO GET THAT.
FATHER.
NOW YOUR PASTOR TAMALE.
(man) ONE KUNG PAO
CHICKEN CHIMALE.
TASTES LIKE A REGULAR TAMALE
JUST WITH A BIT MORE SPICE
TO IT.
NICE AND JUICY, YOU CAN
REALLY TASTE THE CHICKEN.
I WANT TO GET THE TORTA
ON THAT LAST ORDER.
THIS IS A GREAT MIX
OF TWO DIFFERENT KINDS
OF REALLY GOOD FOOD.
SOY GINGER SHRIMP TACO.
MMM. REALLY GOOD.
ULTIMATE L.A. TACO.
IT IS LEGIT.
IT'S AUTHENTIC. IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHEN I HEARD THAT YOU GUYS
WERE DOING THIS,
I'M LIKE, OH, I GOT TO CHECK
THESE CATS OUT.
CARNE ASADA CHOW FUN.
WE'RE HERE TO FEED
THE MASSES.
CONGRATULATIONS.
SURE IS A FUNKY RIG.
NICE JOB.
APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
WAY TO GO.
UP NEXT...
LOCO MOCO SUNNY-SIDE UP.
WE'RE HEADING TO HAWAII...
SHOYU CHICKEN.
FOR THE ISLAND TAKE...
CHILI DOGS OUT.
ON BURGERS AND DOGS.
THAT'S GREAT GRAVY.
THANK YOU.
YEAH, I'M WAITIN' IN LINE.
WHY?
WELL, I HEAR IF YOU WANT
THE BOMB HAWAIIAN FOOD DRIVE-IN
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF WAIKIKI,
THIS IS THE JOINT.
THEY HAVE 48 YEARS OF SERVING UP
HAWAIIAN SPECIALTIES
LIKE SHOYU CHICKEN
AND LOCO MOCO.
THAT'S WHY I'M WAITING IN LINE
HERE AT THE RAINBOW DRIVE-IN.
NAH, I'M SORRY, BRO.
BACK OF THE LINE.
SHOYU CHICKEN.
(man) WHEN YOU COME TO HAWAII,
IT'S ONE OF THE PLACES
YOU HAVE TO COME AND EAT.
ONE MIX PLATE.
THIS IS JUST GOOD LOCAL FOOD.
THANKS TO JIM GUSUKUMA.
...ALL OVER.
WHOSE FATHER-IN-LAW STARTED
THIS JOINT BACK IN '61.
AND WE'VE MAINTAINED IT
ALL THESE YEARS.
IT'S FAST FOOD,
HAWAIIAN-STYLE...
I NEED A SHOYU CHICKEN.
AND IT'S CALLED
A PLATE LUNCH...
TWO SCOOPS OF RICE,
ONE SCOOP OF MAC SALAD
AND THEN WHATEVER
MAIN DISH YOU--
BONELESS CHICKEN,
GRAVY ALL OVER.
THE BBQ STEAK.
NEED A MAHI PLATE.
NOT YOUR STATESIDE STANDARDS
AND THIS...
THE LOCO MOCO.
AIN'T YOUR STATESIDE BURGER.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
RICE AND HAMBURGER AND EGG
WITH GRAVY ON TOP.
GRAVY JUST MAKES
EVERYTHING BETTER.
LET'S GET
THE GRAVY TRAIN GOING
SO WE CAN GET
THE LOCOMOTION GOING.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA GONNA MAKE
SOME CHICKEN STOCK,
WHICH IS THE BASIS
FOR OUR GRAVY.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN STOCK.
ABSOLUTELY.
AT A DRIVE-IN.
YES.
WE START OFF WITH CHICKEN NECKS
AND THIGH BONES.
SECRET INGREDIENT FOR US--
IT'S DRIED SHRIMP.
ONE OF THE FOUNDATIONAL ITEMS
IS DRIED SHRIMP?
YES.
SHH.
FRESH GINGER.
OKAY.
DRIED SEAWEED.
LITTLE KOMBU?
KOMBU, EXACTLY.
THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE ADD WATER,
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
NO BROWNING OF THE BONES...
NO.
NO ADDING VEGETABLES.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA SIMMER?
TWO OR THREE HOURS,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT,
AND USE IT FOR OUR GRAVY.
WE START OFF
WITH TOMATO PURéE.
FOR THE GRAVY?
FOR OUR GRAVY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME CRUSHED GARLIC, SOME SALT.
TOMATO PURéE?
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
CARAMEL COLORING.
TOMATO PURéE?
MORE SECRET SPICES.
HANG ON. I WANT TO SEE THIS.
CHILI POWDER.
YES.
GRANULATED ONION.
GRANULATED GARLIC. SUGAR?
YES.
I'M NOT GONNA SAY
ANY MORE AFTER THAT.
(laughs)
GOT TO KEEP THE INTEGRITY.
THIS IS A SECRET RECIPE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR CHICKEN STOCK.
THIS IS NUTS.
AND THIS IS THE GRAVY THAT
YOU'VE ALWAYS BEEN SERVING?
THIS IS THE GRAVY.
HOW MANY GALLONS OF THIS
DO YOU GUYS MAKE A WEEK?
250, 300 GALLONS A WEEK
PROBABLY, EASILY, I'M SURE.
GRAVY'S REALLY POPULAR HERE.
YOU'RE BRINGING THIS
TO A BOIL,
AND THEN YOU HIT IT
WITH THE FLOUR FLURRY.
YES. THICKEN IT UP.
SIMMER IT A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN IT'S READY TO SERVE.
LET'S MAKE SOME LOCO MOCO.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH TWO HAMBURGER PATTIES.
RIGHT HERE.
IS THERE ONION
ALREADY IN THAT?
YES.
I LIKE IT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA LAY IT
RIGHT HERE.
I'M GONNA PUT SOME GRAVY
ON THAT.
WITH THE TOMATO PASTE.
TRADITIONALLY YOU PUT
A LITTLE BIT ON THE RICE ALSO.
OH, YEAH.
OH, YEAH. TALK IT, DADDY.
THEN THE EGGS GO HERE.
AND THAT'S A LOCO MOCO PLATE.
OKAY.
BROTHER, MAN,
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THAT'S GREAT GRAVY.
THANK YOU.
AND THE PATTIES--PERFECT.
IT'S NICE AND TENDER.
LITTLE BIT OF ONION IN THERE.
I THINK IF PEOPLE LOOK AT IT
AND SAY,
"I'VE HEARD OF LOCO MOCO.
I DON'T KNOW."
COME TRY IT HERE. THAT GRAVY
WILL MAKE A BELIEVER OUT OF YA.
DRIED SHRIMP.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO ME?
THE GRAVY
IS TO DIE FOR. MMM.
LOCO MOCO SUNNY-SIDE UP.
(woman) THE EGGS, HAMBURGER
PATTY, THE GRAVY AND THE RICE
IS JUST DELICIOUS.
IT'S CLASSIC HAWAIIAN FAST FOOD
THAT GOES BACK AS FAR AS
THE WORKING MAN'S LUNCH BREAK.
(Jim) PLATE LUNCHES STARTED
AT LUNCH WAGONS.
THEN IN THE EARLY '60s,
THEY MOVED INTO FIXED LOCATIONS,
RAINBOW DRIVE-IN BEING
ONE OF THE FIRST.
AND ALMOST 50 YEARS LATER...
TWO MIX PLATES.
THEY'RE STILL
CRANKING 'EM OUT...
CHILI PLATE.
1,200 A DAY.
ROAST PORK IS OUT.
THAT'S MORE
THAN 400,000 A YEAR.
I JUST REMEMBER
WHEN I WAS 5 YEARS OLD,
COMING HERE
AND GETTING THIS EXACT LUNCH.
I HAVE THE MIX PLATE--
BEEF, CHICKEN AND MAHIMAHI.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE SHOYU CHICKEN IS OUT.
I LOVE THE SHOYU CHICKEN.
IT'S A SOY SAUCE-BASED
ASIAN-BRAISED CHICKEN.
MMM.
WOW.
MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH CHICKEN.
AND THAT THIS DRIVE-IN...
CHILI DOG'S OUT.
EVEN THIS ONE'S A PLATE LUNCH.
WELCOME TO HAWAII.
THE SPICES ARE PERFECT.
A LOT OF PLACES
TRY TO DUPLICATE THIS,
BUT IT JUST DOESN'T
TASTE THE SAME.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH OUR CHILI.
IT'S ONE
OF OUR BETTER SELLERS.
THE CHILI?
THE CHILI IS.
COUPLE OF INCHES OF WATER
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
FRESH CHOPPED DICED TOMATOES...
OKAY.
DICED ONIONS, FRESH ONIONS,
SOME RECONSTITUTED
DEHYDRATED ONION.
WE USE BOTH...
I HAVEN'T SEEN
THAT ONE BEFORE.
FRESH AND DEHYDRATED.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA BRING
THIS TO A BOIL.
WHEN IT COMES TO A BOIL,
WE'RE GONNA ADD HAMBURGER.
80-20 GROUND BEEF LIKE
YOU MAKE THE BURGERS OUT OF?
80-20. AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
AGAIN.
BREAK UP THE HAMBURGER.
NOW WE'RE READY TO ADD
THE BEANS.
AND IN HAWAII,
IT'S KIDNEY BEANS.
OH, I LIKE KIDNEY BEANS.
AND TOMATO PURéE,
THEN SALT...
A LOT OF IT.
BLACK PEPPER,
LITTLE BIT OF CAYENNE
AND SAME THING WITH CUMIN.
OKAY.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
I LOVE IT HERE.
AND FRESH GARLIC.
THAT'S A GOOD AMOUNT
OF GARLIC.
CHILI POWDER.
THAT'S WHERE THE CHILI POWDER'S
GONE IN THE WORLD.
I FELT THE PRICES RISE.
THEN WE STIR IT ALL UP.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA LET
THIS SIT HERE AND SIMMER?
UNTIL IT COMES
TO A BOIL AGAIN.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
TURN IT DOWN,
PROBABLY ABOUT ANOTHER
20 MINUTES OR SO.
OKAY.
WE SKIM OFF THE FAT.
WE'RE GONNA THICKEN IT UP WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR SLURRY.
YOU LOVE YOUR SLURRY.
THIS IS THE WAY
THAT WE WERE TAUGHT
AND THE WAY THAT
WE CONTINUE TO DO IT.
IT'S THICKENED UP.
WE SIMMER IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
AND IT'S READY TO GO.
LET'S COOK
SOME HOT DOGS.
COUPLE DOGS GO IN
ON THE GRILL.
THIS IS A STAPLE HERE.
YES, AND IT'S GONNA COME ON
A PLATE LUNCH,
'CAUSE THIS IS
A PLATE LUNCH PLACE.
WE SERVE SANDWICHES--
THAT'S THE WAY IT WORKS.
AND ALL OF OUR CHILI DOG PLATES
COME WITH TWO DOGS.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA LADLE
A BUNCH OF CHILI ON IT.
WITH OUR KIDNEY BEANS.
LET'S TRY THE CHILI FIRST.
MMM.
YOU MIGHT HAVE
SOMETHING THERE, BUDDY.
AND WITH THE RICE.
TRY IT WITH THE MACARONI.
SO YOU GET THE COOL
AND THE CREAMY
WITH THE SPICY AND MEATY.
SPICY AND MEATY.
MMM. I TELL YA, THAT RICE
JUST PLAYS IN SO NICELY.
THE RICE IS SO NICE.
CHILI IS DYNAMITE.
MIXING WITH THE MAC SALAD--
RIGHT ON POINT.
MMM. NICE JOB.
CHILI DOG PLATE.
IT'S GREAT.
THIS TASTES REALLY GOOD.
I GREW UP WITH THIS.
THIS WAS THE STAPLE, HUH?
FOR ME.
FOR YOU IT IS. YOU'VE BEEN
EATING HERE 47 YEARS.
MIX PLATE READY.
(man) THERE'S LOTS OF PLACES
THAT COME AROUND AND GO,
BUT RAINBOW IS HERE,
AND IT'S A PART OF WHO WE ARE.
CHILI PLATE,
CHILI DOG.
EAT FOOD, TALK STORY.
THAT'S KIND OF WHAT MAKES
THIS PLACE HAWAIIAN.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
EXCELLENT JOB.
GOOD SHOT. GOOD SHOT.
BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
THAT WAS FUNNY.
GOT TO COME VISIT
THE RAINBOW.
NEXT STOP...
SMOKEHAUS SAMPLER PLATTER.
MINNESOTA...
IT'S GOOD. IT'S PERFECT.
FOR FAST FOOD...
REALLY, REALLY FRESH.
WITH ATTITUDE.
SMOKED WHITEFISH BASKET.
IT IS OUTSTANDING.
YOU KNOW,
EVERYBODY HAS A QUEST.
FOR MONTY PYTHON,
IT WAS THE HOLY GRAIL.
FOR PONCE de LEóN--
THE FOUNTAIN OF YOUTH.
AND FOR GUY FIERI,
IT'S GREAT SALUMI,
YOU KNOW, CURED ITALIAN MEATS.
SO I'M HERE
IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA,
AT THE DeWITT-SEITZ MARKETPLACE
WHERE I HEAR
THERE'S A DUDE INSIDE
THAT IS CURING IT, BRINING IT
AND SMOKING IT.
MY QUEST MAY BE OVER,
AT NORTHERN WATERS SMOKEHAUS.
SALAMINI BASKET.
THEY SMOKE MEAT, CURE IT
AND SALT IT HERE. BEST IN TOWN.
SMOKEHAUS SAMPLER PLATTER.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S PERFECT.
THE BAD BOY
OF THE VIKINGS,
STEVE HUTCHINSON
AND HIS WIFE LANDYN.
I DON'T HAVE A SOLID BODY.
I KNOW MY MEATS.
AND THIS IS GOOD STUFF.
THIS IS...
THE PORK LOIN PROSCIUTTO,
THE SPANISH-STYLE CHORIZO.
AM I IN HEAVEN?
AND IT ALL STARTED...
SPECIAL TO GO.
AS ERIC GOERDT'S HOME HOBBY.
I BOUGHT A SMOKER
AND WAS SMOKING FISH.
THEN 12 YEARS AGO,
HE TURNED PRO.
WE STARTED MAKING
ALL OF OUR OWN DELI MEATS,
AND THEN WE BROUGHT
THE SANDWICH MENU.
THEIR SANDWICHES
ARE WONDERFUL.
LYNN, COME GET
YOUR FRENCH KISS.
HE MAKES EVERYTHING FRESH.
YEP, EVERYTHING.
ITALIENSK, HOUSE-MADE SALAMI.
DeWITT SEITZER
WITH PORK LOIN.
HOT CHORIZO
WITH PEPPERONCINI.
AND GET THIS...
THE BISON PASTRAMI.
TWO PASTRAMI MOMMIES
TO GO.
REALLY JUICY, REALLY FRESH.
OH, I LOVE IT.
BISON PASTRAMI.
NOW I'M MAKING THE BRINE.
SALT,
DEXTROSE--IT'S CORN SUGAR.
THIS IS SODIUM NITRATE,
THE PINK SALT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA STIR THIS UP.
GET READY TO INJECT IT
INTO THE BISON.
LIKE, INJECT IT?
INJECT IT.
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
BISON EYE OF THE ROUND.
EYE OF THE ROUND,
RIGHT.
AND THIS IS A SPRAY--
THIS IS AWESOME.
IT DRAWS UP THE BRINE
AS WE PUMP,
SO IT'S GONNA INJECT
THE BRINE ALL OVER
INSIDE
THE EYE OF THE ROUND.
WOW.
YOU SEE IT EXPANDING?
YEAH.
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
THIS BRINE GETS EVERYWHERE.
THIS KIND OF--
WHOA, IT--
ONCE WE PUMP ALL THESE
WITH THE BRINE,
PUT 'EM IN THIS BUCKET
AND POUR THE BRINE OVER 'EM.
WE'LL ADD A BUNCH
OF FRESH GARLIC.
AND HOW LONG WILL THIS SIT
WITH THIS BRINE IN IT?
FOR SEVEN DAYS.
SEVEN DAYS?
SEVEN DAYS.
YOU'RE JUST ROTATING
BATCHES.
TAKE THIS OFF, YOU'LL SEE
ALL THE GARLIC ON TOP.
GIVE THIS A LITTLE RINSE,
AND THEN WE COAT IT
WITH A COMBINATION OF
BLACK PEPPER AND CORIANDER.
LAY IT ON THICK
AND KIND OF PRESS IT IN.
NOW THIS IS GONNA GO
INTO THE MEAT SMOKER--
THIS IS GONNA GO RIGHT
IN THE MEAT SMOKER, YOU BET.
AND WHAT TEMPERATURE
IS THIS GONNA RUN AT?
IT'S GONNA START AT 130.
GRADUALLY RAISE
THE TEMPERATURE UP.
SO HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO?
PROBABLY ABOUT SIX,
SEVEN HOURS.
THAT'S AWESOME.
AND THESE ARE READY
FOR THE SMOKER.
JUST POP IT IN.
IN WE GO.
THE WOODCHIPS GO HERE.
THIS IS MAPLE
AND HICKORY WOOD,
AND THIS IS CALLED
THE SMOKE GENERATOR.
HOPPER TURNS, DROPS SAWDUST
DOWN ON THAT HOT PLATE,
UNDER WHICH
IS A HEATING ELEMENT,
AND THE FANS SUCK
IT INTO THE SMOKEHOUSE.
AFTER SEVEN HOURS, WE TAKE ALL
THE WRAPS OUT OF THE SMOKEHOUSE
AND WE PUT 'EM IN OUR
WALK-IN COOLER OVERNIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THE COLOR.
EYE OF THE ROUND'S PERFECT,
NOT REAL FATTY.
LOOK, IT'S RAINING!
HUMUNGOUS FLAVOR.
DUDE, YOU SHOULD TRY
DOING THIS PROFESSIONALLY.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PASTRAMI MOMMY.
A LITTLE MAYO,
A LITTLE MUSTARD,
LOTS OF PASTRAMI.
PEPPERONCINIS.
A COUPLE SLICES
OF PROVOLONE,
LETTUCE--
THERE WE HAVE IT.
OH, OH, OH.
I FEEL GUILTY.
I WAS DROOLING.
YOU KILLED THAT.
CAN YOU SEE THE HALO
RIGHT THERE?
LOOK, SHOW 'EM
YOUR WINGS.
(laughing)
OH, MAN.
PASTRAMI MOMMY!
IT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU JUST DON'T NORMALLY GET
BISON IN A LUNCH MEAT FORM.
EVERYTHING IS REALLY,
REALLY FRESH.
AND AS LOCAL AS WE CAN GET.
LIKE THIS ONE--
WHITEFISH BASKET,
PLEASE.
YOU GOT IT.
WHITEFISH IS QUINTESSENTIALLY
LAKE SUPERIOR.
I'VE NEVER HAD
LAKE SUPERIOR WHITEFISH.
WELL, YOU BETTER.
THIS IS THE START OF
THE SMOKED WHITEFISH PROCESS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A VERY SIMPLE BRINE.
10 POUNDS OF SALT,
2 POUNDS BROWN SUGAR.
OKAY.
SO HOW LONG WILL THIS
FISH SIT IN THE BRINE?
TWO HOURS.
AND HOW MANY FISH ARE YOU ABLE
TO DO IN A SMOKER AT A TIME?
TYPICALLY ABOUT 250 POUNDS.
(whistles)
THAT'S A BIG FISH.
BECAUSE WE MADE THAT
REALLY INTENSE BRINE,
BUT IT'S GONNA BE
A SHORT BRINING PROCESS.
RIGHT.
I SCORE THEM SO THAT BRINE
HAS A CHANCE
TO PENETRATE THE FISH,
THEN WE DUMP THE BRINE.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH TO SAY.
I'M JUST SITTING HERE
WATCHING THIS JUST IN AWE.
IT'S--IT'S AWESOME.
COOL.
SO NOW AFTER THE 2-HOUR SOAK,
YOU RINSE THE EXCESS
BRINE OFF OF 'EM,
AND WE RACK 'EM
FOR THE SMOKE HOUSE.
OH, LOOK AT THIS.
SLIDE 'EM IN.
SERIOUSLY,
I WANT TO DRIVE THIS.
OH.
AND IT GOES IN THE SMOKEHOUSE
FOR ABOUT SIX TO SEVEN HOURS.
(deep voice) THE VORTRON.
(whooshing)
(normal voice)
I'M GETTING ONE OF THESE.
LORI'S JUST GONNA HAVE
TO DEAL WITH IT IN THE HOUSE.
ONCE IT SMOKES, THEN WE TAKE
IT IN THE WALK-IN COOLER.
IT COOLS...
YEP, OVERNIGHT, AND THEN
IT'S READY TO EAT.
AWESOME.
I EAT THE WHOLE FISH?
YOU CAN EAT
THE WHOLE FISH.
PEEL THE SKIN BACK,
AND THEN MY FAVORITE
CRACKER IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
ALL WE NEED
IS A COLD BEER.
MMM, YOU GOTTA
BE KIDDING.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S RICH, IT'S FLAKY.
IT IS OUTSTANDING.
YEAH, WHITEFISH HAS
A REALLY CLEAN FLAVOR.
MMM. SO BALANCED.
IT'S NOT SWEET.
IT'S NOT SALTY.
IT'S NOT OVERSMOKED.
IT'S JUST GOT THIS
REALLY NICE,
EASYGOING FLAVOR.
RIGHT ON. AWESOME.
SMOKED WHITEFISH BASKET!
IT'S GREAT. HE JUST
DOES A GREAT JOB.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
TO BUY IT.
BROTHER, YOU DON'T NEED
TO MAKE ANYTHING ELSE.
THEN AGAIN...
SALAMINI BASKET!
AH, SALAMINI--
IT'S LIKE HEAVEN.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
YOU'VE GOTTA SEE THE SAUSAGE
THAT WE'RE GONNA MAKE.
THIS IS OFF THE HOOK!
WHITEFISH BASKET.
AT NORTHERN WATERS SMOKEHAUS
IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA...
THANKS, LUCY.
OWNER ERIC GOERDT
IS SMOKING UP A STORM.
CAJUN FINN
AND WHITEFISH PLATTER!
AND WHEN HE'S NOT SMOKING,
HE'S CURING.
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?
I'LL HAVE THE SALAMINI.
THE SALAMINI--
THAT'S MY PASSION.
OHH!
BY FAR, THE BEST.
(Eric) WE ARE MAKING
OUR HOUSE-MADE
DRY-CURED SALAMINI,
WHICH IS--MEANS
SMALL DIAMETER SALAMI.
OHH!
LET'S ROCK 'N' ROLL.
GROUND BERKSHIRE PORK.
BERKSHIRE PORK.
FROM MINNESOTA.
THE BOMB PORK.
JUST PLAIN OLD SALT.
OKAY.
THEN WE HAVE FENNEL SEED,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
DRY MILK POWDER,
DEXTROSE, CORN SUGAR,
AND THIS IS SODIUM NITRATE--
CURING SALT.
SO WE HAVE A BACTERIAL INHIBITOR
THROUGHOUT THE WHOLE PROCESS.
OKAY.
AND THEN THIS IS JUST GARLIC
PURéED WITH OLIVE OIL.
SO WE MIX THIS REALLY WELL.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE STARTER CULTURE.
AND THE STARTER CULTURE
IS FOR...
THERE'S A FERMENTATION STAGE,
WHICH IS GONNA TAKE ABOUT
TWO TO THREE DAYS...
OKAY.
AND WHAT THAT DOES IS IT EATS
THE SUGARS THAT WE PUT IN THERE
AND IT CREATES LACTIC ACID,
AND THAT LACTIC ACID
WILL LOWER THE pH.
DUDE, THESE ARE ALL
PRESERVATION METHODS...
YEP.
AND NOT TASTE METHODS.
BUT ODDLY ENOUGH, THESE
ARE ALL CONTRIBUTING FACTORS
TO THE FLAVOR PROFILE.
OKAY.
NOW WE PACK IT INTO THIS
SAUSAGE CYLINDER HERE.
LET'S PUT IT UP HERE,
CRANK IT DOWN.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THESE ARE BEEF INTESTINES.
AND DO THEY HAVE A POROSITY,
OR A BREATHE?
THEY DEFINITELY DO,
AND DURING THE PROCESS
WHEN IT'S IN THE DRYING ROOM,
THAT BECOMES REALLY IMPORTANT,
BECAUSE IT ALLOWS
MOISTURE TO ESCAPE.
JUST GONNA CUT IT,
TWIST IT INTO LINKS HERE,
SO IT DOESN'T COME APART.
IT'S GONNA HANG FROM THERE.
AND AT THIS POINT,
WE TAKE A WEIGHT.
HOW MUCH WEIGHT
WILL HAVE BEEN LOST
BEFORE YOU DECLARE
THAT IT'S DONE?
MOST TIMES PEOPLE WILL PULL
IT OUT WHEN IT'S 25% OR 30%,
BUT I THINK 40%,
FOR MY TASTE BUDS, IS PERFECT.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA DIP THEM
IN A PENICILLIN SOLUTION.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE THE PENICILLIN
ON THE OUTSIDE OF BRIE CHEESE.
IT KEEPS THE OUTSIDE
OF THE SALAMI
MOIST IN THE DRYING PROCESS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT IN OUR
FERMENTATION CABINET,
AND THAT'S GONNA LOWER THE pH
OVER THIS 2- TO 3-DAY PERIOD.
WHOA.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
THAT MOLD HAS GROWN,
AND YOU CAN SMELL
THE LACTIC ACID.
PULL THESE OUT OF HERE AND TAKE
'EM INTO OUR CURING ROOM.
NOW THEY'RE GONNA DRY
ABOUT 30 DAYS.
OH, MY GOSH!
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
HANG THESE UP.
THIS IS SO COOL.
ONCE WE GET CLOSE
TO 30 DAYS,
WE'LL BEGIN TO WEIGH THEM--
THAT'S WHERE THE 40% COMES IN--
AND THEN THEY'LL BE READY
TO EAT.
LOVE IT.
THROW THIS UP ON THE SCALE
JUST TO MAKE SURE IT'S READY.
AND YOU WANT TO SLICE THIS
REALLY THIN,
SO IT ALMOST
MELTS ON YOUR TONGUE.
(laughs)
WHAT?
THE FENNEL--RIGHT THERE.
NICE INCORPORATION,
GOOD FAT.
I LOVE THAT
LITTLE TINGE OF MOLD.
I MEAN, THAT COULDN'T BE,
SERIOUSLY, ANY BETTER.
AWESOME.
REALLY.
THAT MEANS A LOT,
COMING FROM YOU.
OH, DUDE.
SALAMINI BASKET!
UNBELIEVABLE.
IT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
REALLY, THE ONLY PLACE
I GO.
TWO PASTRAMI MOMMYS.
IT'S VERY ORIGINAL,
AND EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
AWESOME.
COOL, HOPE
TO SEE YOU BACK.
DUDE, NO QUESTION,
I'LL BE BACK.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(humming)
HEY!