HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
TASTES LIKE BEER
AND TASTES LIKE BEEF
AT THE SAME TIME.
COMFORT FOOD
WITH ATTITUDE.
TWO ORDERS OF GUINNESS STEW.
IN TRUCKEE, CALIFORNIA...
THIS PLACE IS GREAT.
IT'S GOT THAT OLD-TOWN FEEL.
THE VINTAGE DINER...
SANDWICH IN THE WINDOW.
WHERE THEY'RE CLASSIN' UP
THE CLASSICS.
(woman) KOBE MEATLOAF.
THE MEAT IS SO TENDER
AND JUICY.
MMM.
AND EVEN ENGLISH MUFFINS
ARE MADE FROM SCRATCH.
MMM. THAT COMPLETELY WORKS.
NEAR CINCINNATI...
HERE'S SPAGHETTI,
LADLE THE CHILI OVER.
NOW IT'S A 2-WAY.
THE 3-WAY--
CHILI, CHEESE AND SPAGHETTI.
THE 41-YEAR-OLD FAVORITE...
THROW ONIONS ON THERE,
IT'S A 4-WAY.
YOU THROW THE BEANS ON THERE,
IT'S A 5-WAY.
TAKING CINCINNATI CHILI...
GOT A 6-WAY.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
6-WAY, WE TOP IT OFF
WITH OUR BEER-BATTERED
JALAPEÑO BOTTLE CAPS.
WE JUST WENT
FROM RIDICULOUS TO CRAZY.
AND OUTSIDE JACKSONVILLE...
CABBAGE UP.
THE IRISH PUB...
THE BEST IRISH COMFORT FOOD.
DOING THIRD-GENERATION
IRISH CLASSICS...
GUINNESS STEW FOR YOU.
AND BRINGING ATTITUDE...
LAMB SLIDERS UP.
TO PUB GRUB.
I COULD EAT
A HUNDRED OF THOSE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM--
TRUCKEE, CALIFORNIA,
ABOUT 30 MILES WEST OF RENO
AT A VERY IMPORTANT CORNER,
BECAUSE AS LONG AS
I CAN REMEMBER,
IF I WENT THAT WAY,
I WAS GOING
TO NORTHSTAR SKI RESORT,
AND IF I WENT THAT WAY, WELL,
I WAS GOING TO SQUAW VALLEY.
BUT TODAY, I'M GOING THIS WAY,
BECAUSE IT'S NOT TOO OFTEN
WE FIND A 1948 KULLMAN DINER CAR
HERE IN CALI.
THIS IS JAX AT THE TRACKS.
SANDWICH IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S JUST KIND OF
A CLASSIC.
ALL THE CHROME AND THE BAR--
I LOVE SITTING AT THE BAR.
THIS IS AN ORIGINAL, ALL
THE WAY, THROUGH AND THROUGH.
AND WHEN IT CAME UP
FOR SALE...
I CAME IN HERE AND I SAID,
"THIS IS ME."
SO EAST COAST TRANSPLANT
BUD HALEY BOUGHT IT...
COMING RIGHT UP.
FIXED IT UP...
YOU CAME IN,
REDID THE MENU.
REDID EVERYTHING.
AND PUT NEW ZEALANDER
PHIL BROWN IN THE KITCHEN...
WESTERN GOING DOWN.
TO PUT A SPIN
ON THE CLASSICS.
(Phil) CHICKEN FRIED STEAK.
COMFORT FOOD--
IT'S AN UPSCALE TAKE.
MORNING ADDICTIONS.
BALSAMIC VINAIGRETTE
ON TOP OF HASH BROWNS
AND EGGS.
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
THE CORNED BEEF IS HANDMADE.
IT'S THE BEST I'VE HAD.
AND THE EGGS BENEDICT...
BENNY IN THE WINDOW.
HOMEMADE CRAB CAKES
WITH HOMEMADE HOLLANDAISE,
AND HERE'S A NEW ONE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR ENGLISH MUFFINS.
MMM.
I DON'T THINK ON TRIPLE "D"
HISTORY--LET ME THINK.
NO, WE MADE THAT THERE.
NOPE. SO YOU'RE THE FIRST.
OKAY, SO FIRST, WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN OUR ACTIVE DRY YEAST.
OKAY.
SOME SALT,
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR...
BAKING POWDER.
BAKING POWDER,
ADDING WARM WATER.
YOU CAN HEAR IT DANCING.
SOME HOT BUTTER.
OKAY.
AND NOW COLD MILK--
GONNA BRING THAT TEMP DOWN.
YOU'RE SITTING THERE
ACTUALLY HOLDING--
AS OPPOSED TO USING
A THERMOMETER,
YOU'RE JUST GETTING
THE TRUE FEEL.
THAT'S RIGHT. AND JUST GIVE
IT A QUICK LITTLE STIR.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA LET
THAT YEAST START EATING.
YOU CAN SEE THE BUBBLES
STARTING TO RISE TO THE TOP.
TAKE ONE OR TWO MINUTES.
NOW WHAT KIND OF FLOUR
ARE WE GONNA USE WITH THIS?
HIGH-GLUTEN BREAD FLOUR.
BREAD FLOUR SO YOU GET
THAT ELASTICITY,
'CAUSE THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
WE LOVE ABOUT AN ENGLISH MUFFIN
IS BITING INTO IT AND--UHH--
GETTING A LITTLE CHEW.
OKAY, SO NOW OUR MIXTURE
OF YEAST AND SUGAR AND SALT,
ALL THAT STUFF,
THEN WE'LL GET HER MIXING--
FIVE MINUTES OF MIXING. ONCE
SHE'S NOT STICKING TO THE SIDES,
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT OUT,
PUT IT INTO A BOWL, PROOF IT.
COVER IT.
LOOKS LIKE
SHE'S READY TO GO.
KNOCK HER DOWN AND ROLL HER OUT,
ABOUT 1/2 AN INCH THICK.
(laughs) NOW WE'RE GONNA
STAMP OUT OF MUFFIN.
OKAY.
PUT 'EM ON THAT LITTLE FLATTOP
OVER THERE,
BROWN 'EM UP BEFORE WE PUT THEM
IN THE OVEN TO BAKE.
REALLY?
YEAH, THEY'RE STARTING
TO PUFF UP. THEY'RE COOKIN'.
THEY LOOK GREAT.
ONCE THAT'S DONE,
IN THE OVEN--20, 25 MINUTES.
DIG THIS, MAN. OKAY, SO WHAT
ARE WE WORKING ON NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE HOLLANDAISE SAUCE NOW.
OKAY.
EGG YOLKS IN
A LITTLE WHITE WINE VINEGAR.
PUT A DOUBLE BOILER
ON THE STOVE.
WHISK UP THE EGGS
AND THE VINEGAR.
OKAY.
ONCE WE'VE GOT THAT EMULSIFIED,
WE'RE GONNA ADD HOT BUTTER.
KEEP WHISKING. OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
TAKE IT OFF THE HEAT NOW.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME PAPRIKA,
SALT, SOME PEPPER,
WHISK IT A LITTLE BIT MORE,
AND WE'RE ALL DONE, READY TO GO.
NOW CRAB CAKES.
CRAB CAKES.
THIS IS GONNA GO ON TOP OF OUR
ENGLISH MUFFINS THAT WE MADE.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
MARYLAND BLUE CRAB--
BACKFIN AND LUMP--
SAUTéED PEPPERS AND ONIONS...
NICE CHOP ON THOSE.
CHILI FLAKE, CHILI POWDER...
OKAY.
CRUSHED SALTINE CRACKERS...
DIG IT. NICE.
HOT SAUCE, OLD BAY.
IT'S MARYLAND, RIGHT?
AND ONE LITTLE OLD EGG.
TO BIND IT UP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GET IN THERE
WITH OUR HANDS.
YOU WANT TO KEEP
THAT TEXTURE.
GOT IT.
THAT'S IT. SHE'S DONE. JUST
GONNA MAKE LITTLE CRAB CAKES.
INTO THE RING,
IT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
IT LOOKS GREAT, MAN.
CHILL 'EM
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
SO THEY BIND UP
REALLY TIGHT.
COOK 'EM WHEN YOU'RE READY.
ON THE FLATTOP?
ON THE FLATTOP.
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
GET THOSE GUYS ROLLIN'.
THEN OUR ENGLISH MUFFIN.
OKAY. LOOK AT THAT.
NOW THERE'S NOT AS MANY
NOOKS AND CRANNIES IN THERE.
THEY'RE A LITTLE DENSER.
THEY'RE NICE AND CHEWY.
A LITTLE BIT MORE BUTTER,
AND OUR MUFFIN.
I'M GOING OUT
ON THE ULTIMATE LIMB--
HOLLANDAISE AND EGGS JUST SO I
CAN HAVE THE ENGLISH MUFFIN.
AND WE'LL FLIP THEM OVER.
OH, YEAH.
SO ENGLISH MUFFIN
READY TO GO.
NICE LITTLE TOAST
ON THOSE.
CRAB CAKES.
DIG IT. POACHED EGGS.
POACHED EGGS.
BE GENTLE WITH THEM.
HERE COMES ONE OF THE BEST
PARTS--HOLLANDAISE SAUCE.
VERY NICE.
LOOK AT IT, MAN.
YOU MADE EVERYTHING.
YOU MADE THE HOLLANDAISE,
THE ENGLISH MUFFIN, CRAB CAKE.
EVERY DAY.
THIS IS THE EGG--
OOP, AND IT FEEL OFF.
BUT LOOK AT THAT CRAB CAKE.
NOT A LOT OF FILLING THERE.
I'M SURPRISED
IT'S EVEN HOLDING TOGETHER.
MMM.
THAT COMPLETELY WORKS.
OKAY, LET ME TRY
THE ENGLISH MUFFIN.
THAT'S GOT IT GOING ON
THERE, DUDE.
NICE CHEW TO THAT.
IT'S GREAT TEXTURE.
CRAB CAKE NOT OVERPOWERED
BY THE PEPPERS AND THE ONIONS.
HOLLANDAISE IS NICE
AND CREAMY.
OKAY, AND I'M GONNA DO IT
JUST FOR YOU GUYS.
THAT'S EGG.
THERE.
CRAB CAKE BENNY
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S MUCH HEARTIER THAN
A TRADITIONAL EGGS BENEDICT.
WHAT I'M IMPRESSED ABOUT
WAS THAT YOU MAKE
THAT ENGLISH MUFFIN.
HOMEMADE FOOD
WITH A TWIST.
LIKE MAC & CHEESE
WITH JALAPEÑO AND BACON...
IT WAS WONDERFUL.
DILL-ENCRUSTED
FISH SANDWICHES...
LIGHT AND FRESH.
AND THIS CLASSIC.
(woman) MEATLOAF.
THEY'RE DOING THAT
WITH KOBE BEEF.
IT'S JUICY. IT'S FLAVORFUL.
IT HAS A RAISIN SAUCE ON
THE TOP OF IT THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THIS IS
A ROOT BEER RAISIN SAUCE
THAT'S GONNA GO ON THE...
KOBE BEEF MEATLOAF.
OKAY, FIRE IT UP.
SLICED ONIONS,
CRUSHED SHALLOTS.
OKAY, THE ROOT BEER
AND THE...
THE ROOT BEER
AND THE PLUMPED-UP RAISINS.
NOW THEY PLUMP UP
FOR THREE HOURS.
BRING IT UP TO A BOIL.
NOW PUT THIS THING THROUGH IT.
ONCE WE FINISH
EMULSIFYING IT,
THROW IN A LITTLE BIT
OF DEMI-GLACE, SALT AND PEPPER.
IS IT READY?
IT IS READY.
MMM. THAT'S TASTY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SAUTé
OUR HERBS.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL. GONNA
PUT OUR ONIONS IN THE PAN NOW.
FRESH ROSEMARY, PARSLEY,
BASIL, THYME, SAGE.
THE GARLIC, THE MUSTARD,
THE SALT, THE PEPPER.
YEP.
SMELLS GREAT.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
WHAT WE CALL OUR WET MIXTURE.
FIRST, WHOLE EGGS, PASTE,
HALF-AND-HALF, PANKO.
I'M PANKO FAN 101.
SO THAT'S ALL MIXED UP?
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT OUR
KOBE BEEF INTO THE MIXTURE.
SAUTé MIXTURE WE DID BEFORE.
FINALLY, OUR WET MIX.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
MIX THIS UP?
TAKES TWO OR THREE MINUTES.
SO EVERYBODY'S INCORPORATED.
MM-HMM.
WAXED PAPER DOWN. NOW WE'RE
GONNA PORTION THEM OUT.
9 OUNCE PORTIONS OF MEATLOAF.
NOT JUST MEATLOAF,
BUT KOBE BEEF MEATLOAF.
KOBE BEEF MEATLOAF.
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT INTO
A LITTLE BIT OF A FOOTBALL FORM.
YEP. ONTO YOUR SHEET TRAY.
WRAP IT WITH SOME
APPLEWOOD SMOKED BACON.
AND THEN YOU CAN FINISH IT
WITH A BRUSH OF KETCHUP.
HOW LONG WILL THEY
GO DOWN FOR?
BETWEEN 15 AND 20 MINUTES.
HOLD 'EM ON THE LINE AND THEN
WHEN IT GETS READY FOR SERVICE,
HOW ARE WE GONNA HEAT 'EM UP?
SIZZLE PLATTER INTO THE OVEN
20, 25 MINUTES.
PERFECTLY GLAZED UP
WITH THE KETCHUP ON THERE.
THEN LOVELY BROCCOLINI.
CREAMY YUKON GOLD
MASHED POTATOES.
ATTABOY.
AND THE ROOT BEER
RAISIN SAUCE.
HERE IT COMES.
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT OFF
WITH SOME ONIONS.
FIRST I'M GONNA TRY IT
WITHOUT ANY SAUCE ON IT.
MMM.
THAT RED GLAZE
OF THE KETCHUP ON THERE.
CUT INTO IT--IT'S JUICY. NICE
LITTLE KICKER FROM THE BACON.
THAT ROOT BEER RAISIN SAUCE
COMES RIGHT IN THERE.
I THINK MOST PEOPLE WOULD
BE HAPPY JUST TO FIND
A NICE MEATLOAF, BUT WHEN
YOU CAN MAKE MEATLOAF
THE NEXT LEVEL, THAT'S WHEN
YOU'RE DOING IT GREAT. GOOD JOB.
KOBE MEATLOAF.
THE MEAT IS SO TENDER
AND JUICY.
CORNED BEEF REUBEN
IN THE WINDOW.
THIS PLACE IS GREAT.
IT'S GOT THAT OLD-TOWN FEEL,
BUT THEY'VE UPGRADED THE MENU.
DILL-CRUSTED FISH SANDWICH.
(woman) EVERYBODY LOVES
A DINER.
NOW IT'S EASY, CASUAL,
YOU KNOW IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
YOU KNOW WHAT? SOMEONE SHOULD
MAKE A SHOW ABOUT ONE.
UP NEXT...
SPAGHETTI AND THE CHILI
IS A GREAT MIXTURE.
WE'RE HEADING NORTH
OF CINCINNATI...
BOWL OF CHILI?
TO LOAD UP
ON A LOCAL CLASSIC.
YOU GO ANYWHERE IN CINCINNATI,
YOU SAY, "I WANT A 5-WAY,"
I'M GETTIN' SPAGHETTI,
I'M GETTIN' THE CHILI,
I'M GETTIN' ONIONS, I'M GETTIN'
BEANS, I'M GETTIN' CHEESE.
CORRECT.
TEXAS HAS ITS BRISKET.
CALIFORNIA HAS TACOS.
MEMPHIS HAS BARBECUE.
NEW ENGLAND HAS CHOWDER.
WELL,
WHAT DOES CINCINNATI HAVE?
THAT'S RIGHT--
CINCINNATI-STYLE CHILI.
NOW CINCINNATIANS GO THROUGH
MORE THAN 2 MILLION POUNDS
OF CHILI A YEAR
TOPPED WITH
OVER 850,000 POUNDS OF CHEESE.
NOW THERE'S BEEN
A BIG DEBATE--
WHO MADE IT FIRST
AND WHO MAKES IT BEST?
WELL, EVERYBODY
HAS THEIR OPINION,
BUT A LOT OF YOU WROTE IN
AND SENT ME TO A PLACE
THAT I'D NEVER EVEN HEARD OF--
BLUE ASH CHILI,
15 MILES NORTH OF CINCINNATI,
AND MY ONLY QUESTION NOW IS,
AM I'M GONNA HAVE
A 2-WAY, 4-WAY, 5-WAY
OR, AT THIS JOINT, 6-WAY?
GOT A 6-WAY.
'CAUSE STACKING CHILI
ON SPAGHETTI...
2-WAY CHILI COMIN' UP.
IS SOMETHING
FOLKS GROW UP WITH HERE.
THE 3-WAY--
CHILI, CHEESE AND SPAGHETTI.
YOU THROW ONIONS ON THERE,
IT'S A 4-WAY.
YOU THROW BEANS ON THERE,
IT'S A 5-WAY.
YOU GO ANYWHERE IN CINCINNATI,
YOU SAY, "I WANT A 5-WAY,"
I'M GETTIN' SPAGHETTI,
I'M GETTIN' THE CHILI,
I'M GETTIN' ONIONS, I'M GETTIN'
BEANS, I'M GETTIN' CHEESE.
CORRECT.
AND HERE AT BLUE ASH...
BOWL OF CHILI.
THE CHILI HASN'T CHANGED
AT ALL.
NOT SINCE THIS JOINT
FIRST OPENED...
CHILI TO GO.
BACK IN '69.
THE ORIGINAL GREEK OWNERS,
IT'S THEIR RECIPE,
AND IT'S BEEN IN THEIR FAMILY
FOR A LONG TIME.
AND WHEN RESTAURANT VETS
NICK INSCO...
CHEESE CONEY.
AND HIS WIFE CHARLENE
BOUGHT THE PLACE...
HI THERE.
THEY BOUGHT THE CHILI RECIPE
RIGHT ALONG WITH IT.
IT'S A UNIQUE FLAVOR.
IT'S TERRIFIC.
WHEN I SEE SOMETHING
LIKE THIS,
I KNOW THAT YOU'RE EITHER
FEEDING THE TROOPS
OR WE ARE GONNA MAKE
A MESS OF CHILI.
ABSOLUTELY.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA START OFF WITH
ABOUT 100 POUNDS OF GROUND BEEF.
100 POUNDS!
YEP.
FRESH GROUND, NEVER FROZEN?
CORRECT.
FILL IT UP WITH WATER.
WE'LL JUST STIR
INTO A SLURRY.
NOW WE ADD SALT,
GARLIC POWDER.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
TWO HOURS.
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN 100 POUNDS
OF MEAT BOIL.
THAT'S ON GOLDEN MEAT POND.
IT IS. IT'S GOTTA BE
AROUND 250 DEGREES AT LEAST.
SO NOW WHAT GOES IN?
NOW WE PUT IN THE ONIONS.
TOMATO PASTE.
THAT'LL PUT SOME NICE COLOR
IN THIS.
AND THEN CHILI SPICE MIX.
PAPRIKA, TOMATO POWDER,
CUMIN, BLACK PEPPER,
CINNAMON, SALT.
CORRECT.
BUT YOU WON'T TELL ME
THE PORTIONS.
GOT THAT RIGHT.
OR THE LAST TWO INGREDIENTS.
AND ALL WE DO
IS JUST STIR IT UP.
HOW LONG DOES THIS GO?
THAT'S GONNA GO
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND OPEN UP THE LID
AND PUT IN THE SLURRY MIX.
NOW THE SLURRY MIX IS WATER
AND CRACKER MEAL,
AND THAT'S GONNA HELP
TIGHTEN THE CHILI UP.
CORRECT.
RIGHT NOW WE'LL GO AHEAD AND SET
IT FOR ANOTHER 45 MINUTES,
AND THAT'LL STEEP OVERNIGHT.
STAYS ABOVE 140 DEGREES
SO IT'S SAFE.
RIGHT.
AND IT JUST SITS THERE
AND MELDS ALL THE FLAVORS.
CORRECT.
I HEAR THAT THERE'S A LOT OF
TURF WARS HERE IN CINCINNATI,
AND WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU STAND IN THIS?
I THINK WE HAVE
THE BEST CHILI IN TOWN.
FROM THE 2-WAY...
CHILI ON TOP OF SPAGHETTI.
ALL THE WAY
UP TO THE 5-WAY.
BEANS WITH ONIONS
AND CHEESE.
AND BLUE ASH TAKES IT
EVER FURTHER.
6-WAY.
6-WAY, WE TOP IT OFF
WITH OUR BEER-BATTERED
JALAPEÑO BOTTLE CAPS.
SO THESE
ARE PICKLED JALAPEÑO PEPPERS?
CORRECT.
BUILD ME A 6-WAY, BROTHER.
START OFF
WITH YOUR SPAGHETTI.
CHILI.
ALL RIGHT,
SO NOW IT'S A 2-WAY.
NOW IT'S 2-WAY.
ONIONS, KIDNEY BEANS.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND TOP IT OFF WITH CHEESE.
WHOA! WHOA!
BEER-BATTERED
JALAPEÑO BOTTLE CAPS.
JUST WENT FROM RIDICULOUS
TO CRAZY.
LOOK AT THAT BITE
RIGHT THERE. MMM!
THE CHILI
HAS A UNIQUE SPICE TO IT.
THE ONIONS ARE NICE AND FRESH,
AND THE PASTA REALLY WORKS--
COOKED AL DENTE,
WHICH I THINK IS CRITICAL.
HAVING THE BEANS IN THERE,
THERE'S THE TEXTURE
THAT YOU EXPECT
TO SEE IN CHILI,
BUT THE BEANS
ARE A LITTLE BIT MORE WHOLE.
RIGHT.
THEN YOU PUT A RIDICULOUS AMOUNT
OF CHEESE ON IT.
THAT'S A GREAT WAY
TO DO CHILI. MMM!
I COULD EAT THAT
SIX OR SEVEN TIMES A WEEK.
GOT A 6-WAY
AT TABLE 30.
SPAGHETTI AND THE CHILI
IS A GREAT MIXTURE.
NEED A 3-WAY--
ONIONS AND CHEESE, PLEASE.
3-WAY.
THE TEXTURE AND THE TASTE
OF THE TANGINESS--
IT'S GOT
THE REAL CINCINNATI FLAVOR.
6-WAY.
JALAPEÑOS REALLY ADDS
A KICK TO IT.
TONS OF CHEESE.
AND WHAT ELSE DO YOU
LIKE TO HAVE CHILI ON?
PRETTY MUCH ANYTHING.
TWO CHEESE CONEYS PLAIN,
TABLE ONE.
CONEYS WITH
ONIONS AND MUSTARD.
GOT A CHILI LASAGNA.
THE CHILI TASTE REALLY COMES OUT
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I'VE NEVER HAD LASAGNA
THAT HAD NO NOODLES.
THEY'RE TORTILLAS.
(Nick) SIX LAYERS.
IT'S UNIQUE.
IT'S CRAZY.
IT'S GOOD.
WHAT ELSE COULD YOU
POSSIBLY DO WITH CHILI?
WE DO A CHILI PHILLY
AS WELL.
HE'S TRYING TO HURT ME.
NOW SELLING
CHILI PHILLY.
REGULAR PHILLY CHEESESTEAK,
THEY LOAD IT UP WITH CHILI.
AND HOMEMADE ROAST BEEF.
TOP ROUND.
NOW HOW WE GONNA SEASON IT UP?
START OFF WITH
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER, OREGANO,
DEHYDRATED ONIONS, KOSHER SALT,
THYME, CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
AND WE'VE GOT THE ROSEMARY.
MIX IT THOROUGHLY.
DO YOU DRY-RUB THIS IN HERE?
WE GO AHEAD AND POUR OLIVE OIL
ALL OVER THE TOP ROUND,
AND WE DO IT ON BOTH SIDES.
RUB IT UP.
AND THEN WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND TAKE OUR SPICE MIXTURE HERE
AND GENEROUSLY PUT IT
ON BOTH SIDES.
WRAPPED UP
AND HOW WILL THIS MARINATE?
THIS WILL MARINATE OVERNIGHT.
LET IT SIT FOR A LITTLE BIT
AND THEN ROAST AT WHAT?
WE ROAST IT AT 275
FOR ABOUT 4, 4 1/2 HOURS,
DEPENDING ON THE SIZE
AND THE WEIGHT.
LET IT REST.
CUT IT
INTO MANAGEABLE PIECES.
YEP. CUT IT IN HALF
AND THROW IT IN THE SLICER.
WE'RE GOING FOR A THIN SLICE
OF MEAT.
LOOK HOW THIN THAT IS.
WE'RE ABOUT TO MEDIUM THERE.
HOW ARE WE GONNA
HEAT IT UP?
FRESH-BAKED BUN
WITH SOME BUTTER ON IT.
A LITTLE WEIGHT ON IT,
GET A NICE CRISP ON THERE.
THROW DOWN OUR ROAST BEEF.
WE'LL SEASON THAT MEAT OFF.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
SAUTéED GREEN PEPPERS,
RED PEPPERS AND SOME ONION,
SAUTéED MUSHROOMS
THAT ARE SAUTéED WITH BUTTER
AND JACK DANIEL'S WHISKEY.
THERE YOU GO.
JACK DANIEL'S IN THERE.
SO IT'S YOUR TYPICAL
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
YEP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA LAY
OUR PROVOLONE CHEESE OVER IT.
WOW.
REALLY BUILDING THAT UP.
PUT THE STEAMER LID
OVER THERE.
A LITTLE STEAM
HELPS MELT THE CHEESE.
ABSOLUTELY.
THEN ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS
INVITE 15 OF YOUR BEST FRIENDS
OVER TO COME EAT IT.
THAT'S RIGHT. TAKE OUR BUN
OFF THE GRILL THERE.
GOT THAT. YOU'RE MAKING
THAT LOOK EASY. NOW THE CHILI.
NOW WE'RE GONNA LADLE
THE CHILI OVER.
THIS IS WRONG.
THAT'S OUR CHILI PHILLY.
HOW MUCH DOES IT WEIGH?
3 POUNDS?
A GOOD COUPLE POUNDS.
OH. THE PHILLY ON ITS OWN--
TASTY.
NICE TOASTED BUN,
FRESH VEGGIES IN THERE.
THE CHILI--
DUDE, IT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU'RE SHOWING CINCINNATI CHILI
CAN GO ON JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
CHILI PHILLY WITH FRIES.
I'M A BIG CHEESESTEAK FAN,
AND IF YOU ADD CHILI
TO THE TOP OF IT, WHEW!
CHILI PHILLY.
PUTTING CHILI ON TOP--
ICING ON THE CAKE.
PHILADELPHIA,
MEET CINCINNATI.
BENGALS PLAY THE EAGLES.
LOOKS LIKE THE BENGALS
ARE WINNING, THOUGH.
THEY'RE JUST SMOTHERING
THE COMPETITION!
(Nick)
GOT A CHILI CHEESE FRY.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THIS IS
MY COUSIN "G-BOMB."
THIS GUY CAN EAT.
TAKE HIS WORD FOR IT.
6-WAY CHILI.
IT'S THE BEST.
JUST MAKE IT WITH LOVE
EVERY DAY.
YOU GUYS CONTINUE TO KEEP
KNOCKING OUT THE CHILI.
THANK YOU.
GOOD JOB, BUDDY.
THANKS.
NEXT UP...
LAMB SLIDERS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO NORTHERN FLORIDA...
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
FOR THAT COASTAL CLASSIC...
TWO ORDERS OF GUINNESS STEW.
WHAT ELSE? BEEF STEW.
PHENOMENAL.
SO YOU GUYS
ARE SO GONNA DIG THIS ONE.
HERE I AM IN ATLANTIC BEACH,
ABOUT 15 MILES OUTSIDE
OF JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA,
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT
WAS A DREAM OF FOUR SISTERS.
NOW PEOPLE AROUND HERE
SAY THAT THEY ARE RUNNING
THE REAL-DEAL IRISH PUB
IN A STRIP MALL.
THIS IS CULHANE'S IRISH PUB.
HEY, LADIES.
SHEPHERDS PIE.
I JUST LOVE THIS PLACE.
THE BEST IRISH COMFORT FOOD.
CABBAGE UP.
CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE--
JUST INCREDIBLE.
THEY KNOW WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
'CAUSE THEY GREW UP ON IT.
THE CULHANE SISTERS--
THEY ARE AWESOME.
THAT WOULD BE MARY JANE,
MICHELLE,
LYNDA AND AINE CULHANE...
THANK YOU.
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT
TO SERVE THE FOOD THEY LOVED.
BRISKET FROM IRELAND--
WHAT OUR MOTHER COOKED,
WHAT OUR GRANDMOTHER COOKED.
SO THEY BROUGHT IN LONG-TIME
FRIEND AND HEAD CHEF...
THANK YOU.
OLIVE DAVIS.
I TRICKED HER. I WAS LIKE, "COME
ON. I JUST NEED YOU PART-TIME."
AND THEN
I SUCKED HER IN.
AND NOW...
TWO ORDERS OF GUINNESS STEW.
SHE'S CRANKING OUT
ALL THE FAMILY FAVORITES.
COME ON,
THE GUINNESS STEW.
TASTES LIKE BEER AND TASTES
LIKE BEEF AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S JUST SO SUCCULENT, IT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH. I LOVE IT.
SO WHAT
ARE WE GONNA MAKE FIRST?
OUR HOUSE SEASONING BLEND--
PUT IT IN GUINNESS BEEF STEW.
WHITE PEPPER, BLACK PEPPER,
DRIED OREGANO,
DRIED BASIL, GARAM MASALA,
CURRY POWDER, CLOVE...
GOT IT.
NUTMEG.
WOW, THAT'S A LOT OF NUTMEG.
IT IS. KOSHER SALT,
ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
DRY MUSTARD.
SUGAR.
AND MONTREAL STEAK SEASONING.
NO.
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S A ROASTED,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
ROASTED GRANULATED GARLIC.
YES.
WHO MADE THIS?
UH, ME. I DID.
I DID, YEAH.
WHAT DID YOU DO,
JUST EENY, MEENY, MINEY...
NOW YOU JUST--NOW WAIT UNTIL
YOU SEE IT ALL MIXED UP.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE IT
ALL MIXED UP.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN I MIX IT UP?
GO!
ALL RIGHT. AND IT DOES
GO IN EVERYTHING.
WAIT TILL YOU TASTE OUR
BEEF STEW. YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
TOP BOTTOM ROUND.
GOOSENECK.
YEAH.
A LOT OF FLAVOR,
A LOT OF CONNECTIVE TISSUE.
MM-HMM.
DEFINITELY IS ONE
OF THE KINDS OF MEAT
THAT YOU WANT TO TRIM,
CLEAN UP AND COOK A LONG TIME.
YEP.
SHE SLICES, SHE DICES,
SHE CHOPS.
SO WE CUBE ALL THIS UP.
MEAT'S ALL CUT.
MARINATE IT OVERNIGHT
IN GUINNESS BEER...
LOOK AT THAT.
OUR HOUSE SEASONING BLEND,
FRESH THYME.
USE IT THE NEXT DAY
AND TENDERIZED ENOUGH
FOR US TO COOK IT
IN THREE, FOUR HOURS.
OH, LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT.
I AM MAKING OUR DEMI-GLACE.
VEAL BONES.
WOW, WE'RE GETTING SERIOUS
ABOUT THE DEMI.
I AM. OIL--HELP BROWN 'EM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
HELP 'EM BROWN UP, RIGHT.
YEAH. CARROTS, ONIONS,
LEEKS, CELERY.
POP HER IN THE OVEN.
HOW MANY HOURS DO WE GO?
DROP HER IN.
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF
IN THE OVEN.
HOLDS IT DOWN
WITH HER FOOT.
KITCHEN WARRIOR. READY?
I'M READY.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, WHOA!
IT'S ROAST TO THE MOST.
SOME RED WINE TO GET THE FOND
OFF THE BOTTOM OF THE PAN.
SHE'S SERIOUS.
TRANSFER THE VEAL BONES
TO A STOCK POT.
MORE WINE, WATER.
IN?
IN.
AND HOW OFTEN ARE YOU
MAKING THIS A WEEK?
ONCE OR TWICE.
THE GIRL COOKS!
A BOUQUET GARNI.
WE'VE GOT SOME ROSEMARY
AND SOME BAY LEAF.
PEPPERCORN AND WHATNOT.
MORE GUINNESS.
MORE GUINNESS, OH, YEAH.
TOMATO.
A LITTLE BIT
OF TOMATO PASTE.
THAT COOKS FOR, YOU KNOW,
SIX TO EIGHT HOURS DEPENDING--
ADD WATER
A COUPLE MORE TIMES?
OH, YEAH. AND THEN WE
JUST KEEP IT ON REAL LOW.
AND THEN WE'LL TAKE IT
AND STRAIN IT, COOL IT,
SKIM THE FAT
AND READY TO GO.
EXACTLY. AND READY TO GO.
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
GUINNESS BEEF STEW.
OIL IN.
OH, WE'RE HOT.
THAT'S HOT.
HERE YOU GO!
(sizzling)
I USUALLY LIKE TO STAND
RIGHT UP THERE IN A FIRE SUIT.
WELL, YOU CAN'T TELL IF THERE'S
ANY GUINNESS COMING OUT OF IT.
THE MEAT LIKES GUINNESS, TOO.
I MEAN, I CAN SMELL IT.
"MEAT LIKES GUINNESS."
THEN WE ADD IN OUR ONIONS,
CARROTS
AND THE CREMINI MUSHROOMS.
SWEAT IT DOWN
FOR ABOUT ANOTHER HOUR.
THE FLOUR GOES IN
TO MAKE THE ROUX.
STIR THAT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I HAVE UND GALLON. I DON'T KNOW
WHERE I GOT GERMAN FROM.
OH, YEAH. LOOK AT THAT.
I LOVE IT.
(deep voice) LUKE.
(normal voice)
WOW, THAT SMELLS GREAT.
BARLEY.
AND THAT'S JUST THICKEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT AS WELL?
YEAH.
ADDING A BOUQUET GARNI.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SEASONING BLEND AGAIN.
THEN WE ADD THE--
I'LL GO UP HIGH LIKE YOU DID.
LOOK AT THE DEMI.
YOU COULD RUN YOUR HEMI
ON THAT DEMI.
AND THEN
IT COOKS DOWN AGAIN.
JUST LET IT REDUCE.
IT THICKENED UP.
WHOA!
THE MEAT ALL BROKE DOWN.
IT'S ALL GUINNESS-Y.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS A GOOD, YOU KNOW,
FULL-BELLY DISH.
OH, YOU CAN SMELL
THAT GUINNESS. MMM.
THIS IS RICH, FLAVORFUL,
FULL OF DEPTH.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH,
CHEF GUY.
REALLY NICE, ROUNDED,
ROASTED FLAVOR.
THE CARROTS
PLAY IN PERFECTLY.
A LITTLE VELVETY TEXTURE
FROM THE MUSHROOMS.
AND THE MEAT--
COMPLETELY JUST
DISSOLVES-IN-YOUR-MOUTH TENDER.
THANK YOU.
GREAT JOB. SO IMPRESSED.
PHENOMENAL.
THANK YOU.
AND THE GUINNESS STEW
FOR YOU.
I LOVE IT.
THE BEEF IS JUICY.
IT IS THE BOMB.
IT IS.
IT'S ALWAYS
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
POTATO-LEEK SOUP.
THE POTATO AND LEEK SOUP,
I LOVE.
THE FOOD IS AUTHENTIC.
DINGLE FISH PIE.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
NAMED FOR
AN IRISH FISHING VILLAGE
80 MILES
FROM WHERE THE SISTERS GREW UP.
(woman) THE DINGLE FISH PIE
FOR YOU.
WHAT IS IN DINGLE FISH?
SALMON, COD AND SHRIMP.
THERE IT IS.
HOLY BOATLOAD OF SEAFOOD,
CAPTAIN.
I KNOW. I KNOW IT.
WOW. GIRL, YOU'RE ON POINT
WITH THIS.
IF YOU DIG ALL THE WAY
TO THE BOTTOM OF IT,
YOU'LL FIND A MEMBERSHIP CARD
TO A LOCAL GYM.
(Olive) DINGLE FISH PIE UP.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S RICH AND FLAVORFUL.
IT TASTES FANTASTIC.
THE BANGERS AND MASH--
THEY'RE MY FAVORITE.
BANGERS AND MASH.
ACROSS THE BOARD,
THE MENU IS OUTSTANDING.
WHO CAME UP
WITH THE RECIPES?
PRETTY MUCH
A GROUP DECISION.
AND THE GROUP DECIDED,
EVEN AT THIS IRISH PUB...
ANOTHER GUINNESS?
NOT EVERYTHING
HAD TO BE IRISH.
LOTS OF BEACH. I MEAN,
WE'RE AT THE BEACH.
THE WINGS
ARE ABSOLUTELY AWESOME.
AND THEN THERE'S OLIVE'S TAKE
ON THE ALL-AMERICAN BURGER...
LAMB SLIDERS UP.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT OLIVE DOES,
BUT IT'S GREAT.
LITTLE BURGER. OH.
I COULD EAT A HUNDRED
OF THOSE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL START
COOKING MORE.
ONE DOWN.
THE GUINNESS BEEF STEW
FOR YOU.
AT CULHANE'S IRISH PUB,
THE CULHANE SISTERS
HAVE TURNED
HEAD CHEF OLIVE DAVIS LOOSE...
SHEPHERDS PIE.
TO DO THE IRISH COMFORT FOOD
THEY GREW UP WITH...
GOOD IRISH FOOD.
AND SOME BAR FOOD CLASSICS.
GLAZED WINGS ARE AWESOME.
WITH A TWIST.
LAMB SLIDERS UP.
IT JUST TASTES
SO, SO GOOD.
LAMB SLIDERS.
I LOVE LAMB.
SO WE HAVE FRESH GROUND LAMB,
MINCED RED ONION.
SO THAT'LL
REALLY INCORPORATE EASILY.
YES.
WHOLE GRAIN MUSTARD.
COME OUT.
MINCED GARLIC,
FRESH OREGANO...
VERY NICE.
AND OUR
HOUSE SEASONING BLEND.
THIS HOUSE SEASONING BLEND...
YEAH.
CAN I BUY A JAR OF IT
UP FRONT?
SURE CAN.
CAN YOU?
DO YOU HAVE IT FOR SALE?
NO, NO.
SERIOUSLY, YOU SHOULD.
THAT'S IT?
YOU DON'T WANT
TO OVERWORK IT.
SHE DIDN'T OVERWORK IT,
SO WHEN IT COOKS,
IT'S NOT GONNA EXPEL
ITS FAT.
OUR NEXT STEP IS WE
WEIGH THEM OUT AT 3 OUNCES.
3 1/2.
THEY'RE DEFINITELY
NOT UNDER-PORTIONED HERE.
YEAH, WE'RE LIBERAL.
THERE WE GO. THERE WE GO.
THERE WE GO. SAME PLACE.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
(whistles)
THAT'S A HOT FLATTOP.
IT IS.
SO THESE WILL GO FAST.
ABOUT TWO OR THREE MINUTES
TO BROWN THEM
ON BOTH SIDES PROPER.
AND I WANT TO COOK YOU
A GOOD MEDIUM, YOU KNOW.
THEY SMELL AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT,
THEY'RE COOKIN'.
GO! (imitates whip cracking)
NOW WE HAVE
TO BUILD THEM.
CURRY AIOLI,
WHICH WE MAKE.
(whispers) MAYONNAISE.
LETTUCE,
TOMATO,
LAMB BURGER ON THERE,
RED ONION.
JUST...
PUT THE OLIVE ON THERE.
I GOT TO FINISH IT--
CHIPOTLE AIOLI.
MMM!
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A STEP-AWAY BURGER.
YOU NEED A NAPKIN?
I NEED A BIB.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
I COULD EAT A HUNDRED OF THOSE.
THERE'S NOTHING ABOUT THAT
I WOULD CHANGE.
HANDS-DOWN PERFECT.
THANK YOU.
THE KICKER--
THE MACK DADDY CRUST.
YOU OWN THAT. OHH!
I'D DO A DANCE OR SOMETHING
IF I WAS YOU.
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED
TO DANCE A JIG?
I DON'T KNOW. CAN I?
(laughs) YOU ROCK.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THAT'S AWESOME.
AMAZING.
LAMB SLIDERS UP.
REALLY DELICIOUS.
ANOTHER GUINNESS FOR YOU?
JUST BRILLIANT--
COME IN HERE
AND HAVE A GUINNESS
AND HAVE A LAMB SLIDER.
IT'S JUST THE BEST.
YOU CAN ORDER
ANYTHING ON THE MENU.
GOOD, YOU'RE HAPPY. GOOD.
BUT IT'S THE HOSPITALITY.
IT'S A GREAT TIME
EVERY TIME YOU'RE HERE.
HEY, MARY!
THIS IS REALLY LIVING
THE AMERICAN DREAM,
WHAT WE'RE DOING,
AND IT'S--IT'S INCREDIBLE.
WE'RE SO BLESSED.
I'M TELLING YOU, THERE SHOULD BE
MUSIC IN THE BACKGROUND.
ABSOLUTELY.
NICE JOB.
NICE JOB, LADIES.
THANK YOU.
(women) THANK YOU.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHAT? I SOMETIMES EAT TWO
WHEN WE DO THE SHOW.
HEY! GO AWAY!
(laughs)