HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LOBSTER PIE IS UP.
OLD-TIME ATTITUDE.
MAINE THE WAY
I REMEMBER IT.
ON
ST. SIMONS ISLAND, GEORGIA...
THIS PLACE IS
THE REAL DEAL.
THE BARBECUE JOINT...
THE BEST BARBECUE
I'VE EVER HAD.
WHERE THEY'RE
SMOKING IT UP...
LOOK AT THE SMOKE RING
ON THIS, YOU GUYS. OH!
OLD-SCHOOL.
ALL WOOD--THIS GUY
HAS GOT IT ON.
IN NASHVILLE...
HERE'S YOUR HAM, SIR.
THANK YOU.
THE 27-YEAR-OLD
SOUTHERN KITCHEN...
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS--
ORDER UP.
TAKING YOU BACK IN TIME...
MEATS AND THREE.
WITH TRUE SOUTHERN CLASSICS.
ENTRéE PLUS THREE VEGETABLES--
JUST EXCELLENT.
AND IN MAINE...
THIS IS DEFINITELY
THE BEST.
THE '50s LANDMARK...
SEAFOOD CHOWDER.
WHERE A COUPLE
OF BROTHERS...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ARE DOING COMFORT FOOD...
FRESH SEAFOOD--YOU CAN'T
GET IT ANYWHERE ELSE.
THE NEW ENGLAND WAY.
MMM, THAT IS SO KILLER
WITH NO FILLER.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO CHECK IT OUT--
ST. SIMONS ISLAND, GEORGIA,
RIGHT BETWEEN JACKSONVILLE
AND SAVANNAH, GEORGIA.
A FEW THINGS YOU CAN EXPECT
WHEN YOU GET HERE--
GREAT BEACH RESORTS,
RIGHTEOUS GOLF
AND TWO DUDES THAT ARE DOING
OLD-SCHOOL BARBECUE.
WE'RE TALKING
COOKING ONLY WITH WOOD
ON OUTDOOR PITS.
THIS IS SOUTHERN SOUL.
THEY USE NOTHING BUT WOOD,
AND THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
THE OAK WOOD THEY USE--
IT'S A VERY UNIQUE SMOKE.
LOOK AT THAT--
THE ENTIRE BARBECUE PROCESS
IS DONE BY ALL WOOD--
THIS GUY HAS GOT IT ON.
THAT'D BE OWNER
HARRISON SAPP...
(Harrison)
THERE WE GO.
WHO HONED HIS SKILLS BACKYARD
COOKING FOR HIS FAMILY,
ESPECIALLY SON BRENT...
GIVE ME SOME OF THAT.
THERE WE GO.
UNTIL HIS BUDDY
GRIFFIN BUFKIN CALLED.
THAT'S A HOT FIRE.
GRIFFIN WAS LIKE, "HEY,
HARRISON, YOU WANT TO OPEN UP
A RESTAURANT?"
WE HAD ABOUT 700 BUCKS
BETWEEN THE 2 OF US...
AND A SMOKER.
SO THEY PUT IT TO WORK...
THEY LOOK GOOD.
AWESOME.
AT THIS OLD
1940s GAS STATION.
YOU CAN SEE IT SMOKING
RIGHT IN THE MORNING
WHEN YOU'RE GOING TO WORK.
YOU CAN SMELL IT.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
MMM. I USUALLY GET
THE PULLED PORK.
IT'S THEIR TOP SELLER.
IT'S MOIST AND TENDER.
PULLED PORK PLATE!
AND THEY'RE GOING THROUGH
ABOUT A TON A WEEK.
(Harrison)
I GOTTA PLATE!
THE RUB THEY USE IS UNIQUE.
YOU GET A SALT,
THE SAVORY, THE SWEET.
EVERY DAY
YOU MAKE THE RUB.
EVERY DAY.
FROM SCRATCH.
SO TURBINADO SUGAR--
DOESN'T BURN AS EASY.
AND IT MAKES
A GOOD CRUST.
IT'S THE NATURAL SUGAR.
OKAY.
KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
PAPRIKA,
GARLIC.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION.
GRANULATED ONION,
THYME LEAVES,
CUMIN.
AND THE WHOLE BOATLOAD
OF LIGHT BROWN SUGAR,
WHICH GIVES
THE SUPER SWEETNESS.
SWEET IS BETTER.
SWEET IS BETTER. OKAY.
AND WE JUST MIX IT UP.
WE REALLY LEARNED FROM YOU
AND TRIPLE "D"--
PUT IT IN A BAG
AND MIX THE WHOLE THING UP.
BEST METHOD
IN THE WORLD.
BEST METHOD IN THE WORLD.
THAT'S--NO, SERIOUSLY.
BUT DON'T DO IT IN SOME
CHINTZY LITTLE PLASTIC BAG.
MY BUDDY DID THAT--
PUT IT ALL IN THERE,
SHOOK IT APART--SPLIT OPEN,
WENT EVERYWHERE IN THE KITCHEN.
STILL DIGGING SUGAR
OUT OF THE GROUT LINE, OKAY?
HOW WE LOOKING? IT'S ALL
MIXED TOGETHER NICE AND EVEN.
SO NOW WE'RE READY TO START
RUBBING SOME BUTTS?
RUBBING SOME BUTTS.
(whistles) DON'T GET
TO SAY THAT EVERY DAY.
(laughing)
SO WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE TOP SHOULDER OF THE PIG
WITH THE BONE IN.
EXACTLY.
WE RUB 'EM ALL DOWN,
MAKE SURE WE GET IT
IN ALL THE CRACKS.
NOW YOU GONNA LEAVE 'EM
BE FOR A BIT,
OR DO YOU
JUST RUB 'EM--
THEY SPEND THE NIGHT
IN THE WALK-IN.
A LITTLE TIME
TO PERMEATE, OKAY.
EXACTLY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE
THESE THINGS.
ONE OF 'EM
RIGHT HERE.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
DO YOU RUN THIS?
225 TO 250.
10 TO 14 HOURS--
NOW GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
I MEAN, I'M A BASTER.
JUST APPLE JUICE.
JUST--
HOW MANY TIMES ARE YOU BASTING
THESE THROUGHOUT THE COURSE?
PROBABLY EVERY HOUR.
EVERY HOUR.
WE DONE, BOSS?
(whistles)
WE ARE ALL DONE.
PULL 'EM OFF.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THE BARK
BUILT FROM THAT TURBINADO SUGAR.
AND HERE'S THE KEY.
WHEN THAT BONE SLIDES OUT
LIKE THAT,
YOU KNOW THAT YOU ARE DONE,
AND YOU KNOW THAT YOU'VE
DONE IT REAL DEAL.
REAL DEAL.
LOOK AT THE SMOKE RING
ON THIS, YOU GUYS. OH!
THEN YOU'VE GOT THIS
SUPER-TENDER PORK THERE.
YOU GOTTA TRY--YOU WANT
TO TRY THIS? ALL RIGHT, GO.
(laughing)
GOOD STUFF, HUH?
PULLED PORK PLATE!
IT'S JUST REALLY FRESH
AND JUICY.
PULLED PORK
WITH FRENCH FRIES.
SOME OF THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
VERY GOOD SMOKE FLAVOR,
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
BRUNSWICK STEW
AND COLLARD GREENS.
I LOVE EVERYTHING
THEY HAVE HERE.
I'VE GOT WINGS DOWN.
I KNOW IT'S FRESH.
I KNOW IT'S GOOD.
I KNOW HARRISON'S
WORKING HIS TAIL OFF.
PUTTING THE RIBS ON!
WITH SO MANY DIFFERENT
SMOKERS OUT THERE,
ARE YOU RUNNING THEM
AT DIFFERENT TIMES OF THE DAY?
I HAVE A BUTT ONE
WITH THE BRISKET,
THEN I HAVE ANOTHER ONE
THAT RUNS FOR RIBS.
SLAB OF RIBS!
THE RIBS
ARE THE BEST.
JUST TENDER,
CAN'T BE BEAT.
SO WE PULL
THE SILVER SKIN
ON THESE ST. LOUIS RIBS,
WHICH IS A SPARERIB THAT'S BEEN
CUT DOWN TO BE UNIFORM.
WE'VE GOT OUR RUB THAT WE USED
WHEN WE DID THE BUTTS.
NOW WHAT'S HAPPENING?
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
MORE SUGAR TO THE RUB.
REASON BEING?
I LIKE IT TO GET
A GOOD CRUST ON IT,
AND THAT--THAT HELPS.
OKAY.
NOW I'M GONNA SPRINKLE 'EM.
I WON'T RUB 'EM.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
SPRINKLE 'EM.
A LOT'S JUST TOO MUCH.
THAT'S PROFOUND.
ONCE AGAIN--
ONCE AGAIN, IT'S OUTDOOR--
REALLY, SOCRATES?
"A LOT IS
JUST TOO MUCH."
JUST TOO MUCH.
SO WE'RE GONNA SET 'EM UP
FOR 20 MINUTES
AND GO TO THE SMOKER.
HERE WE GO.
(Guy) WHAT INTERNAL TEMP
ARE YOU LOOKING FOR?
(Harrison)
BETWEEN 165 AND 175
THESE ARE GONNA GO ON
FOUR TO FIVE HOURS?
EXACTLY.
THESE ARE GONNA
BE MONEY, DUDE.
NOW TELL ME
ABOUT THE DOUBLE STACK.
I'LL LET THE FAT
FROM THIS ONE RENDER
AND GO ONTO THE FAT OF THIS ONE,
AND THEN I'LL FLIP 'EM ALL.
EVERYTHING'S BETTER WHEN IT'S
COOKED IN ITS OWN FAT.
WE'RE JUST KIND OF LETTING
THAT FAT RENDER DOWN,
BASTING EACH OTHER
WITH ITS OWN FAT.
RIGHT, AND THEN EVERY 20 MINUTES
HIT 'EM WITH APPLE JUICE.
SO WE'RE DOING
SOME BASTING.
YEP.
THEN WE'LL COME BACK AND HIT 'EM
WITH SUGAR AND HONEY.
WITH WHAT?
MORE SUGAR AND HONEY.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
WE GOT A FRIEND
THAT DOES IT ALL.
IT'S AN ALL-NATURAL
TUPELO HONEY.
REALLY?
THAT MUCH HONEY, DUDE?
OH, YEAH, WE DO THAT,
AND THEN, 'CAUSE WE DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH, MORE SUGAR.
OH, YOU GUYS,
WE FORGOT TO TELL YOU,
WILLY WONKA OPENED UP
A BARBECUE PLACE.
(laughing)
THIS IS GONNA CANDY UP,
AND THESE THINGS
ARE JUST GONNA COME OUT
EXTRA RIDICULOUS?
EXACTLY.
ALL RIGHT, IS IT TIME
TO PULL 'EM?
TIME TO PULL 'EM.
THESE LOOK RIGHTEOUS,
JUST BREAKING APART
A LITTLE BIT THERE.
THAT IS ST. LOUIS-STYLE, BABY.
THAT'S BIG STUFF.
OKAY, SERVE 'EM IN TWOS?
SERVE 'EM IN TWOS,
SLIT 'EM
SO WE CAN PULL 'EM APART WHEN WE
SERVE 'EM, JUST LIKE THAT.
GOING OVER HERE.
WHY ARE WE PUTTING 'EM
ON THE GRILL?
JUST TO FINISH 'EM OFF. WE'RE
GONNA PUT SOME HONEY ON 'EM
AND THEN GRILL 'EM.
MORE HONEY?
MORE HONEY.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT
THIS EXTRA HONEY.
WE DO LIKE IT SWEET.
ALL FOR YOU THERE, MR. GUY.
THAT'S A MESS
OF RIBS, DUDE.
LOOK AT THE BARK
ON THAT.
IT'S TENDER.
IT'S TOTALLY COOKED RIGHT.
LET ME SHOW YOU
MY LITTLE TEST.
SEE WHERE I BITE
INTO IT?
SOMETIMES WHEN PEOPLE
STEAM THEIR RIBS TOO MUCH,
ALL THE MEAT COMES RIGHT OFF.
SO IT STILL HAS TEXTURE.
IT'S A BIG, MEATY PORTION.
WOW. THOSE ARE SWEET.
BUT ONCE YOU GET INTO
THIS HOT SAUCE OVER HERE--MMM.
WHY I LIVE IN CALIFORNIA--
I'D WEIGH A LOT MORE
IF I LIVED
CLOSE TO YOU GUYS.
WHOLE RACK OF RIBS!
EVERYTHING THAT YOU
WOULD WANT OUT OF A RIB.
(Griffin) RIB PLATE!
IT'S GOT THE SWEET
SOUTHERN FLAVOR.
GOOD FRIENDS, GOOD TIMES--
I COME HERE ALMOST EVERY DAY.
BEST BARBECUE
I'VE EVER HAD.
GOOD-LOOKIN' RIBS.
THEY LOOK GOOD.
THIS PLACE IS
THE REAL DEAL.
YOU WERE BORN
TO BARBECUE, SON.
THAT'S ALL I DO.
SERIOUSLY.
THAT'S IT.
SO MUCH SO THAT WHEN THIS PLACE
BURNED TO THE GROUND
TWO WEEK AFTER WE VISITED,
THEY TURNED RIGHT AROUND,
OPENED AT ANOTHER JOINT
AND STARTED REBUILDING
THE ORIGINAL.
KEEP IT REAL
AND STAY WITH THE WOOD
AND STAY WITH OUR HEARTS AND--
AND THE CRAFT OF--OF SMOKING.
YOU GUYS WALK THE TALK HERE,
SO CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
(man) HERE'S YOUR SIDE
OF TURNIP GREENS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO NASHVILLE...
THEY'VE GOT THE BEST
TURNIP GREENS IN TOWN.
FOR SOME OLD-TIME ATTITUDE
SOUTHERN-STYLE.
COLLARD AND TURNIP.
YEAH.
MMM. I LIKE... (sighs)
SUPER TASTY, BRO.
♪♪
I'M HERE ON 8th AVENUE SOUTH,
ABOUT A MILE
FROM DOWNTOWN NASHVILLE
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT'S WON
A JAMES BEARD AWARD.
I MEAN, THESE GUYS
ARE KNOCKING IT OUT
WITH THEIR HOMEMADE SELECTIONS
OF THE SOUTHERN TRADITION
MEAT AND THREE.
THIS IS ARNOLD'S.
ORDER UP--MEAT LOAF
WITH CREOLE SAUCE.
MEATS AND THREE.
ENTRéE PLUS THREE VEGETABLES--
JUST EXCELLENT.
HERE'S YOUR HAM, SIR.
THANK YOU.
COUNTRY FRIED STEAK, AND THEN
THERE'S ALL KINDS OF VEGETABLES.
GREEN BEANS, TURNIP GREENS
AND MASHED POTATOES.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES--
THEY'RE JUST AMAZING.
WHAT MAKES THE PLACE
SO GOOD?
THIS IS WHAT WE
GREW UP ON AS KIDS.
JUST LIKE KAHLIL ARNOLD...
(Kahlil) BRINGING OUT
THE ROAST BEEF.
WHOSE PARENTS JACK AND ROSE...
EVERYTHING OKAY?
BOUGHT THIS PLACE
27 YEAR AGO.
I STARTED LEARNING
WHEN I COULD BARELY SEE
THE TOP OF THE TABLE.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES,
YOU SAID?
AND THESE DAYS,
HE'S RUNNING THE KITCHEN.
THE MAIN THING IS
IF THEY LIKE THE FOOD,
DON'T CHANGE ANYTHING, SO I'VE
LEFT THE CORE STUFF THE SAME.
LIKE HIS DAD'S OLD RECIPE
FOR THIS ONE.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS--
ORDER UP.
I GOTTA SEE SOME
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
SO HOW DO WE
MAKE IT HERE?
WE BAKE THE CHICKENS
FOR WEDNESDAY.
WE HAVE BAKED CHICKEN
ON THE MENU.
MY DAD WANTED TO INCORPORATE
LEFTOVERS INTO AN ENTRéE,
NOT TO WASTE THE FOOD,
SO HE STARTED DOING
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
CRAM EVERYBODY IN.
PUT A LITTLE WATER IN THE PAN
TO KIND OF BRAISE IT.
I'M GONNA COAT IT
WITH A LITTLE MARGARINE,
SO THAT THE SEASONING STICKS,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
CHILI POWDER, BROWN SUGAR,
A LITTLE PAPRIKA.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
350 FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND 20
TO AN HOUR AND 30 MINUTES.
PULL THAT OUT.
DRAIN IT.
THAT'LL GET SHREDDED.
AND WE'LL START BUILDING
THE GRAVY.
YEAH.
GOT IT.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH A LITTLE MARGARINE.
MELT THAT DOWN.
SAUTé A LITTLE CELERY.
WE'RE GONNA DO
A LITTLE ONION.
WHEN HE SAYS LITTLE,
HE MEANS LITTLE.
A LOT OF GARLIC--YOU'RE
GETTING A LOT OF THE SEASONING
THAT'S ALREADY BEEN
IN HERE.
IN THE CHICKEN.
YES, THE LEFTOVER DRIPPINGS
FROM THE BAKED CHICKEN.
STIR THAT AROUND.
AFTER ALL THE VEGETABLES
HAVE BEEN SAUTéED,
GONNA ADD SOME WATER TO IT,
MORE GARLIC.
VERY NICE.
WE LIKE THE GARLIC HERE.
BLACK PEPPER, WHITE PEPPER,
POULTRY SEASONING,
WHICH HAS GOT, YOU KNOW...
OKAY.
A LITTLE SAGE.
THE SAGE--
BIG KEY.
MIX THOSE SEASONINGS.
ADD A LITTLE CHICKEN BASE.
CHICKEN FLAVOR
AND SALT.
THE NEXT THING WE ADD
IS THE CHICKEN.
A LOT OF BIG FLAVOR COMING
OUT OF THE BONES
AND THE SKIN.
OH, YEAH. YEP.
BOIL THE CHICKEN
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR.
SO YOU'RE GONNA COOK IN THIS
AND FORTIFY THIS STOCK.
YEP.
STRAIN THAT OUT.
SO YOU SUPPLEMENT
WHAT YOU HAVE LEFT OVER
FROM WEDNESDAY.
EXACTLY. GOT IT?
NOW WE'VE GOT OUR CLEAR STOCK
READY TO WORK WITH.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE DUMPLINGS.
DIG IT.
I DO MY ALL-PURPOSE
AND SELF-RISING.
I'M WEARING BLACK.
YOU HAVE FLOUR.
I'M GONNA STAND BACK.
YOU'RE USING A COMBO,
'CAUSE ALL-PURPOSE
WOULDN'T RISE.
IT WOULD JUST MAKE
A HARD ROCK.
YEAH.
SPRINKLE
A PINCH OF SALT.
PLEASE TELL ME THAT IS
STRAIGHT-UP LARD.
OH, THIS IS
YES.
THIS IS WHERE YOU'RE GONNA GET
THAT REAL UNCTUOUS FLAVOR.
WE'RE BASICALLY MAKING
BISCUITS.
WE'RE GONNA CUT THAT LARD
INTO THAT FLOUR
AND TIGHTEN IT UP
WITH SOME ICE WATER.
YEAH.
WE GOT THE RIGHT
CONSISTENCY HERE.
NOW WE'LL FLOUR THE BOARD, ROLL
IT OUT AND MAKE THE DUMPLINGS.
YOU GOT IT.
YOU GOT A ROLLING PIN,
SON? YEAH, YOU DO.
YES, SIR. YES, SIR.
LOOK AT THAT. HOW LONG
HAS THAT BEEN AROUND?
SAYS IT RIGHT THERE--
IT SAYS, "LEGALLY STOLEN
FROM ABE LINCOLN."
IT'S IMPORTANT WE PUT
A LITTLE EXTRA FLOUR ON 'EM,
BECAUSE IT HELPS THE, UH,
STOCK THICKEN UP.
YOU'RE NOT TOO WORRIED
THAT IT'S EXACT SIZE.
YOU JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
THEY DON'T STICK TOGETHER.
YEAH.
YOU LOOK AT THIS
LITTLE SQUARE RIGHT NOW,
THIS THING'S GONNA BECOME
ABOUT THAT BIG,
ABOUT THAT BIG AROUND.
IT'S GONNA BE AWESOME.
ADD THESE IN HERE.
GOT TO STIR 'EM IMMEDIATELY--
RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
OR THEY'LL STICK.
YOU GOT IT.
LOOK HOW THEY
START TO PUFF UP.
(whispering)
I WANT TO EAT THAT.
THESE COOK FOR ABOUT
15 TO 20 MINUTES.
THEN WHEN THERE'S
ABOUT TEN MINUTES LEFT,
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE CHICKEN
SO THE CHICKEN HEATS BACK UP.
JUST TAKE THE WHOLE PAN,
DUMP IT IN THERE. WHY NOT?
GOOD TO GO.
(normal voice)
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT.
OH, MAN. OH, HO.
IT'S THICKENED UP
REAL GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
DUMPLING RIGHT THERE. MMM.
THAT'S ABOUT AS OLD-SCHOOL
AS YOU'RE GONNA FIND.
OH, YEAH.
SOME OF THAT ROASTED CHICKEN
IN THERE--MMM.
I'M JUST STALLING
SO I CAN SHOVEL IT ALL IN.
IT'S A NICE DAY OUT.
THESE ARE GOOD SPOONS.
CREAMINESS,
TENDER CHUNKS OF CHICKEN--
I ALMOST FINISHED THE WHOLE BOWL
IN THAT TIME.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
GOOD JOB.
APPRECIATE IT, MAN.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS
ARE REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
THEY MAKE 'EM LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
THERE YOU GO, DARLIN'.
IS THIS OLD-SCHOOL MEATS
AND THREE THAT YOU REMEMBER?
YES.
(man) ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
TELL ME ABOUT
THE JAMES BEARD AWARD.
IT WAS AMAZING. IT WAS LIKE
BEING AT THE ACADEMY AWARDS.
IN A CATEGORY THAT CELEBRATES
WHAT THEY DO BEST.
IT'S CALLED
"AMERICA'S CLASSICS."
PERFECT SOUTHERN
RESTAURANT.
MASHED POTATOES
AND GRAVY.
I LIKE THEIR SIDES,
AND I CAN'T CHOOSE JUST THREE,
SO I GET FIVE.
(Guy) WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE
THING ON THE MENU?
TURNIP GREENS.
TURNIP GREENS?
THEY'VE GOT THE BEST
TURNIP GREENS IN TOWN.
I THINK HE PUTS
SOMETHING IN 'EM.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THEY DO--COLLARD GREENS.
COLLARD AND TURNIP.
YEAH. WE START OFF
WITH A POT OF WATER,
PUT A LITTLE SUGAR
IN THERE.
IS THIS WHAT
I THINK THIS IS?
IT IS.
YOU'VE GOTTA
BE KIDDING ME.
IT IS. YES.
WASABI POWDER
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE?
BELIEVE IT OR NOT.
NEXT THING WE'RE GONNA ADD--
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE RED PEPPER, SALT.
AND THEN WASABI POWDER'S
NOT ENOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE HORSERADISH
TO ALSO GIVE IT ANOTHER BITE.
WE'RE GONNA WHISK THIS ALL UP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT IN TUNA FISH.
WHAT THE HECK
IS THAT?
THAT'S HAM BASE.
VEGETARIAN GREENS.
THERE'S A LITTLE MARGARINE.
NEXT THING WE'RE GONNA ADD--
A LITTLE HOG JOWL.
HOG JOWL?
YES, SIR.
YOU JUST DUMPED IN SOME
PREMIUM CHEEKS OF THE PIG.
OH.
JULIENNED ONION TO IT--
WE ADD A LITTLE TURNIPS.
LET THIS JUST WARM UP
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES,
JUST KIND OF MELT
EVERYTHING DOWN.
OKAY, FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA
ADD IS THE COLLARD GREENS.
THAT MIGHT LOOK
LIKE A LOT,
BUT AS SOON AS THAT HITS
THAT SIMMERING WATER,
IT IS GONNA START
TO SHRINK DOWN.
SO THIS WILL GO
FOR FIVE, TEN MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'LL GO IN
WITH THE TURNIP.
YEP, TAKES 'EM A LOT LONGER
TO ABSORB THE FLAVOR.
SO WE STIR THOSE UP.
NOW HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET THESE SIMMER FOR?
HOUR AND A HALF TO TWO HOURS--
THE LONGER THEY COOK,
THE MORE THEY'LL ABSORB
THE FLAVOR.
THE WASABI POWDER
AND HAM BASE--I CAN'T WAIT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
THOSE LOOK GREAT.
SERVE IT UP.
QUIT TALKING ABOUT IT.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER.
HERE IT IS.
MMM.
I LIKE... (sighs)
YOU GOT A LOT GOING ON THERE.
THESE DON'T EAT AS A SIDE.
THEY ALMOST EAT AS A MEAL.
SUPER TASTY, BRO. MMM.
WE GOTTA MAKE
THE GREEN MOVEMENT.
IT'S GOOD STUFF.
DIFFERENT GREEN MOVEMENT,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I MEANT.
GOT YOUR SIDE
OF TURNIP GREENS.
TURNIP GREENS
ARE AMAZING,
'CAUSE THEY HAVE, LIKE,
A SMOKY, MEATY FLAVOR.
EARTHY, GREEN, HEALTHY.
EARTHY, GREEN,
HEALTHY PIG JOWL.
THEY'RE PERFECT.
MACARONI AND CHEESE, GREEN
BEANS, ROAST BEEF--ORDER UP.
I EAT THE SAME THING
EVERY DAY.
WHEN I WALK IN,
THEY FIX MY PLATE.
ROAST BEEF?
YOU GOT IT.
VERY GOOD.
VERY, VERY GOOD.
WHAT CAN I GET
FOR YOU TODAY?
YOU GUYS ARE REALLY PUTTING
YOUR HEART AND SOUL INTO THIS.
YEAH.
THIS HAS GOT FAMILY TRADITION.
THIS HAS GOT FAMILY RECIPES.
THERE WE GO.
CONGRATULATIONS.
NICE JOB, MAN.
APPRECIATE IT.
THANKS.
NEXT STOP,
WE'RE HEADED TO MAINE...
THIS IS DEFINITELY
THE BEST.
TO LOAD UP...
LOBSTER PIE.
ON LOBSTER.
MMM. BOY,
THAT IS RICH CITY.
♪♪
HERE'S ONE OF THE THEMES
WE'VE SEEN ON TRIPLE "D" BEFORE.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
HE VISITS THE JOINT AS A KID.
THEN HE FINDS OUT IT'S FOR SALE.
HE DROPS EVERYTHING HE'S DOING,
AND HE BUYS IT
TO KEEP THE LOCAL LEGEND ALIVE.
SO HERE WE ARE IN WELLS, MAINE,
ABOUT 4 MILES SOUTHWEST
OF KENNEBUNKPORT,
TO TRY SOME NEW ENGLAND
COMFORT FOOD.
WELCOME TO MAINE DINER.
SEAFOOD CHOWDER IS UP.
GOOD CHOWDER,
LIKE MAINE IN A BOWL.
HOT LOBSTER ROLLS.
WHAT MAKES
NEW ENGLAND COMFORT FOOD?
FRESH SEAFOOD--YOU CAN'T GET IT
ANYWHERE ELSE LIKE YOU CAN HERE.
LOBSTER PIE.
YOU HAVE TO TRY
THE LOBSTER PIE.
BAKED STUFFED HADDOCK.
HOME COOKING LIKE GRANDMA
USED TO MAKE.
JUST THE WAY MYLES HENRY...
HERE WE GO.
AND HIS BROTHER DICK
REMEMBER IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE HAD A CHANCE TO EAT HERE
WHEN WE WERE YOUNGSTERS.
WE LOVED IT HERE, TOO.
SO WHEN THEY HEARD
THIS '50s LANDMARK
WAS FOR SALE...
EVERYONE ALL SET
FOR NOW?
WE PUT TOGETHER SOME SEED MONEY
AND PUT AN OFFER IN.
(Dick) FEBRUARY OF '83
WE OPENED THE DOORS.
AND QUICKLY BUILT
A REPUTATION.
SEAFOOD CHOWDER IS UP.
NICE AND CREAMY,
VERY DELICIOUS.
"AWARD-WINNING CHOWDER."
"AWARD-WINNING."
WE WON SEVEN YEARS
IN A ROW
AT ONE CONTEST.
GOOD ENOUGH FOR ME.
THE KEY
TO THE SEAFOOD CHOWDER
IS TO COOK EVERYTHING
IN THE SAME BROTH.
ADDING ALL THESE
INGREDIENTS?
WE DO THEM
ONE AT A TIME.
LOBSTERS GO FIRST--
LIVE MAINES,
NOT CHUNK O' LOBSTER?
NO. COOK FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
LET 'EM COOL DOWN.
CRACK 'EM AND PULL
ALL THE MEAT OUT.
THE KEY INSIDE OF THIS
IS TOMALLEY,
WHICH IS KIND OF LIKE
THE LOBSTER'S LIVER.
IT HAS THAT TRUE, DEEP,
RICH LOBSTER FLAVOR.
IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT.
THEN WE DO THE CLAMS.
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES--
WHEN THE CLAMS ARE OPEN,
THEY'RE DONE.
KEEP THE SAME BROTH.
LET 'EM COOL DOWN,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
SHUCK THE MEAT
OUT OF 'EM.
NOW THE SCALLOPS.
THEY GET COOKED.
THEY'RE PULLED OUT, BROTH
IS LEFT, AND THEN SHRIMP--
LAST, ADD THE SHRIMP.
ALL RIGHT, ALL THE SEAFOOD'S
BEEN BLANCHED.
NEXT WE'RE MAKING A BASE
FOR OUR SEAFOOD CHOWDER.
START WITH SALT PORK.
A TRADITIONAL CHOWDER IN MAINE
IS--GENERALLY STARTS
WITH SALT PORK.
GOT IT.
ONION. NOW WE'RE
GONNA ADD BUTTER.
YOU'RE NOT CARAMELIZING
THE ONIONS.
NOT REALLY
YOU'RE JUST TURNING 'EM
TRANSLUCENT.
JUST GONNA TURN 'EM--YEP.
FLOUR'S NEXT.
MAKING A LITTLE
BLOND ROUX.
JUST A LITTLE BLOND ROUX.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME PAPRIKA
AND WHITE PEPPER.
THEN YOU DON'T HAVE BIG,
DARK GRANULES OF BLACK PEPPER.
OKAY.
EXACTLY. THIS IS
A DICED SEA CLAM.
THE SMALLER THE BETTER
SO IT'S TENDER?
YEP.
TIGHTEN IT UP.
AND LAST,
SOME CLAM JUICE.
TAKES ABOUT FOUR MINUTES
TO TIGHTEN UP.
TO KIND OF
MAKE A PASTE?
YEP.
NOW IT'S TIME
TO PUT IT TOGETHER.
SO THE FIRST THING IS GONNA BE
COOKED SCALLOPS.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT THEY WERE
CALLED "SCAWL-LOPS," DID YOU?
COOKED SHRIMP. THEN WE'RE
GONNA ADD OUR CHOWDER BASE.
SHUCKED CLAMS.
AND WE'RE LEAVING 'EM WHOLE?
LEAVING 'EM WHOLE--
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
THIS IS LOBSTER MEAT.
DID I JUST SEE TOMALLEY
GOING IN IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
TOMALLEY'S CRITICAL.
THIS IS ONIONS
AND SALT PORK MIX.
EXACTLY. TWO MORE INGREDIENTS--
HALF-AND-HALF
AND THE LAST ITEM--
THIS IS OUR STRAINED BROTH
THAT WE COOKED ALL THE SEAFOODS
IN. THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
AND THAT'S IT.
TAKES ABOUT 20 MINUTES,
AND IT'S READY TO GO.
HOLY CLAMS. WHY DON'T YOU GET
A LITTLE BROTH IN THE CHOWDER?
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF LOBSTER
AND THE SCALLOPS.
MMM, THAT IS REALLY DYNAMITE.
IT IS RICH. IT IS CREAMY.
THE SEAFOOD IS TENDER.
I AM BLOWN AWAY
BY HOW MUCH SEAFOOD IS IN HERE.
THAT IS SO KILLER
WITH NO FILLER.
MMM, I SEE WHY YOU WIN.
THEY ONLY WAY YOU COULD LOSE
IS IF THE OTHER GUY HAD $50 BILL
CROUTONS FLOATING AROUND.
SEAFOOD CHOWDER.
BIG SCALLOPS IN IT,
CHUNKS OF LOBSTER--
REALLY ONE OF THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
ONE LOBSTER ROLL.
I HEARD THE SCHOOL LUNCHES
IN MAINE,
THE KIDS GET TO EAT
LOBSTER NUGGETS.
I THINK YOU HEARD WRONG.
BUT THEY MIGHT AS WELL.
LOBSTER MACARONI
AND CHEESE.
THIS IS THE EAST COAST OF MAINE.
THIS IS LOBSTER COUNTRY.
IT'S DEFINITELY FRESH.
LOBSTER STEW.
LOBSTER STEW IS
MY ALL-TIME FAVORITE.
(Myles) THE LOBSTER CLUB.
ANYTHING ELSE YOU LIKE
ON THE MENU?
LOBSTER PIE.
IT'S MAINE
THE WAY I REMEMBER IT.
LOBSTER PIE IS UP.
THIS IS MY GRANDMOTHER'S
VERSION
OF A BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER
WITHOUT THE SHELL.
I LIKE THE WAY
THAT SOUNDS.
START OFF WITH MELTED BUTTER,
FRESH SQUEEZED LEMON JUICE.
HERE'S THE KEY TO THE STUFFING
OF THE LOBSTER PIE...
GET OUT.
THE TOMALLEY.
DO PEOPLE KNOW
THEY'RE GETTING THAT?
THEY DO NOW. THEN WE'RE GONNA
WHISK THIS UP A LITTLE BIT.
WHISK THAT UP
WITH THAT HANDY-DANDY
WHISK-A-SPOON.
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
YOU'LL BE ABLE
TO FIND THIS
COMING OUT OF BED, BATH & BEYOND
SOON--THE WHISK-A-SPOON.
OKAY, CRACKER CRUMBS.
RITZ?
CRUSHED RITZ. NEXT BUTTER
THIS CASSEROLE DISH
ADD THE LOBSTER MEAT.
THE LOBSTER MEAT'S
ALREADY COOKED.
BINGO.
HOLY LOBSTER, BATMAN.
NOW TOP IT WITH TOMALLEY,
BUTTER, RITZ CRACKER.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S READY TO GO.
SIMPLE, STRAIGHTFORWARD,
LET THE LOBSTER BE
THE LEAD IN THE SHOW.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
AND WE'RE GONNA BAKE THIS
FOR HOW LONG AT WHAT TEMP?
ABOUT 10 MINUTES
AT 450.
ONCE IT GETS GOLDEN BROWN,
IT'S READY TO GO.
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT.
THE BREADING REALLY HAS
A NICE TENDER CRUST,
JUST FALLING APART. MMM.
BOY, THAT IS RICH CITY.
YOU GET A LOT OF FLAVOR
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
IT'S A CREAMY CRUNCHINESS,
TOMALLEY ADDS TO THAT.
TOMALLEY REALLY BRINGS
THE DISH TOGETHER.
I THINK IF YOU COME
TO THIS PLACE,
AND YOU DON'T TRY THIS ONE,
YOU'RE MISSING OUT.
YEAH, I WOULD
TOTALLY AGREE.
LOBSTER PIE.
VERY TASTY, JUST LIKE EATING
A FRESH MAINE LOBSTER.
LIKE A LITTLE DESSERT PIE,
BUT THEN YOU HAVE LOBSTER IN IT.
(sighs)
OH, IT'S SO GOOD.
JUANITA, YOU'RE UP!
IT'S WHAT YOU GET
AT HOME FROM MOM.
BAKED SCALLOPS.
DEFINITELY HOMEMADE FOOD.
90% OF OUR RECIPES ARE
FROM MY MOM AND MY GRANDMOTHER.
LIKE THIS ONE...
I HAVE
TWO COD CAKES UP.
THAT'S SO LOCAL...
THEY'RE AMAZING.
MOST FOLKS
OUTSIDE OF NEW ENGLAND
HAVE NEVER HAD A CHANCE
TO TRY 'EM...
THAT'S A SURPRISER
RIGHT THERE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
♪♪
AT MAINE DINER
IN WELLS, MAINE...
ENJOY.
BROTHERS MYLES...
LOBSTER MAC COMING UP.
AND DICK HENRY...
TAKE THESE
TO 21 FOR ME.
ARE CRANKING OUT
COMFORT FOOD...
COD CAKES COMING UP.
NEW ENGLAND-STYLE.
FOR US, COMFORT FOOD
IS LOBSTER PIE,
THE SEAFOOD CHOWDER.
AND THIS NORTH ATLANTIC
CLASSIC...
CODFISH CAKES.
POTATO AND SALT COD PATTIES
DATING BACK CENTURIES.
LOOKS DELICIOUS, TASTES
DELICIOUS, TOO. IT'S VERY GOOD.
NEW ENGLAND-STYLE
CODFISH CAKES.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND BOIL
SOME POTATOES AND SOME SALT COD.
SALT COD IS COATED
IN A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF SALT,
ALMOST TO THE POINT
OF FISH JERKY.
I MEAN, IT IS
SUPER PRESERVED.
THIS DOESN'T HAVE TO COOK LONG,
ONLY ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
MORE TO PULL THE SALT
OUT OF IT THAN ANYTHING.
THAT'S ENOUGH--EXACTLY.
SO THE POTATOES AND THOSE ARE
COMING UP ABOUT THE SAME TIME?
YEP.
COOL THOSE AND START
TO MAKE THE CAKES?
ABSOLUTELY.
GOT IT.
PUT THE COD IN THE ROBOT COUPE
AND SHRED IT.
GOT IT.
INTO THE MIXING BOWL WE'RE
GONNA PUT OUR BOILED POTATOES
AND THE BUTTER,
SOME SALT.
WHITE PEPPER?
WHITE PEPPER.
AND WHOSE RECIPE?
THIS IS, UH, THIS IS ACTUALLY
MY GRANDMOTHER'S RECIPE ALSO.
GOT IT.
HALF-AND-HALF IS NEXT,
EGGS, POTATO PEARLS.
POTATO PEARLS IS A FANCY WORD
FOR FREEZE-DRIED POTATOES.
IT REALLY BINDS IT UP.
ADD SOME SAUTéED ONIONS
AND SALT COD.
REALLY SHREDDED
THAT UP.
YEP.
SO WE'RE GONNA
MIX THIS UP.
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE.
I CAN SMELL
THE SALT COD FROM HERE.
YOU CAN.
THAT'S ENOUGH?
YEAH, SO NOW WE'RE MAKING
THE ACTUAL CODFISH CAKE PATTIES.
THAT'S A HEALTHY PORTION.
IT IS INDEED.
YOU WANT ME
TO SQUISHY THE PAPE-Y?
IF YOU'D LIKE TO SQUISH
THE PAPER, PLEASE DO.
SEE THE TEAMWORK?
BEAUTIFUL. GIVE IT JUST
ONE SLIGHT PRESS DOWN.
POP IT IN THE FREEZER
SO THEY REALLY
TIGHTEN UP.
YEP, UNTIL WE'RE
READY TO FRY THEM.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
LET ME INTRODUCE YOU
TO WHAT A TRUE PROFESSIONAL
DREDGING STATION IS LIKE.
YOU GOT THE CHICKEN,
GOT THE SHRIMP, THE CLAM STRIPS,
THE SCALLOP. YOU COULD MAKE IT
ALL HAPPEN FROM HERE.
GO AHEAD AND TAKE YOUR COD CAKE,
SUBMERGE IT IN THE EGG WASH.
AND THEN WE GOT
THE FRY FLOUR.
IT'S A CORNMEAL FLOUR.
YOU DO WET HAND-DRY HAND
WITH THIS?
I DO WET HAND-WET HAND.
THERE YOU GO.
SO YOU GET BIG
KING KONG FINGERS.
ABSOLUTELY.
GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE SHAKE.
PUT IT IN THE BASKET.
AND GET THE SECOND COD CAKE--
SAME PROCESS. SHAKE IT OUT.
AND YOU CAN GO AHEAD AND DROP
THAT IF YOU'D LIKE.
BYE-BYE.
WHEN THEY START
TO FLOAT,
AND THEY GET
A NICE GOLDEN BROWN--
IT TAKES ABOUT FOUR,
FOUR AND A HALF MINUTES.
AND THEY'RE READY. KIND OF
DEGREASE THEM A LITTLE BIT.
THEN I'M GONNA
SET 'EM RIGHT HERE.
THAT'S HOW IT GOES.
SALTED COD WITH BOILED POTATO.
THIS IS AN OLD
NEW ENGLAND RECIPE,
YOU KNOW,
BACK PRE-REFRIGERATION DAYS.
MMM. THAT'S A SURPRISER
RIGHT THERE.
ANYBODY THAT'S EVER HAD
SALTED COD KNOWS
IT'S JUST LIKE, WOW,
BUT THIS HAS LITTLE SNAPS
OF THE SEAFOOD,
A LITTLE SALTINESS.
IT'S SMOOTH, AND IT'S CREAMY.
THAT'S COMFORT FOOD 101.
NICE JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
THIS GUY.
ONE COD AND BEANS.
CREAMY TEXTURE TO IT,
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
COD AND BEANS.
(woman) THE OUTSIDE'S
VERY CRUNCHY AND NICE.
MMM, THEY'RE VERY GOOD.
CODFISH CAKES.
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HADDOCK IS UP.
(woman) I USUALLY GET
THE BAKED HADDOCK.
ABSOLUTELY
MAINE COMFORT FOOD.
ONE LOBSTER ROLL.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
THE BEST.
THE FACT THAT YOU
CAME HERE AS KIDS,
YOU DROPPED EVERYTHING
YOU WERE DOING TO BUY THE JOINT
TO KEEP
THE LEGEND ALIVE...
SEAFOOD CHOWDER.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT WE WANT
TO SEE ON TRIPLE "D."
THANKS FOR THE INVITE.
OH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE REALLY ENJOYED IT.
DICK, THANKS A LOT, BUDDY.
THANKS A LOT, GUY.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
COME MEET THESE CATS.
YOU'LL DIG 'EM.
WHAT A GREAT ROAD TRIP.
BUT DON'T WORRY, WE GOT
PLENTY MORE PLACES TO CHECK OUT.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
CARAMELIZED SUGAR
AND PIG FAT.
PUT IT ON. IT SMELLS GREAT,
LOOKS LIKE A MILLION BUCKS.
OH, MY... (laughing)