HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOA. WHOO.
BURGERS AND MORE.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR
SUZUKAKIA.
"SUZUK" IS MEATBALL.
YEAH.
LEARNIN' SOME GREEK
RIGHT HERE.
IN TRUCKEE, CALIFORNIA...
ONE ITALIAN STALLION.
THE BURGER JOINT...
HEY, GUYS, HOW ARE YOU?
WHERE IT'S FRESH...
ORGANIC AND LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
FAST...
AN ITALIAN STALLION.
AND FUNKY.
(man) THE CHILI HAS
PEANUT BUTTER IN IT.
PEANUT BUTTER'S GONNA
GO IN THE CHILI?
YEAH.
THAT'S AN ALL-AMERICAN
BURGER. MMM.
IN KANSAS CITY, MISSOURI...
GOT AN ORDER UP
ON A STEVE MARTIN.
WHERE IT'S BURGERS GONE WILD...
TEMPURA BATTERED.
MMM.
AND GRILLED CHEESE TO MATCH.
TWO GRILLED CHEESE,
A BURGER, A FRIEND EGG...
(whistles) MMM.
AND IN NASHVILLE...
THE FOOD HERE IS
JUST INCREDIBLE.
A FAMILY RESTAURANT...
OOH.
DOIN' BURGERS WITH
A GREEK TWIST...
(man) LAMB BURGER IS UP.
AND ROLLIN' OUT...
KOTOPITA.
THE OLD FAMILY COOKBOOK.
GREEK POTPIE.
YOU SEE IN THE BAKERY
LIKE A DOUGHNUT.
IN THE MORNING?
YEAH.
OH, SEE? THAT'S MY KIND
OF BREAKFAST.
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP RIGHT HERE
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
IN TRUCKEE, CALIFORNIA,
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF EAST
OF SACRAMENTO.
NOW CHECK THIS STORY OUT.
A DUDE THAT OWNS A COUPLE
RESTAURANTS HERE IN TOWN
ALSO DONATES A LOT OF HIS TIME
TO A HUNGER RELIEF AGENCY.
SO HE FINDS THIS LOCATION WHERE
HE CAN STORE THE DONATED FOOD
THAT HELPS FEED OVER
28,000 FAMILIES A YEAR.
AND TO TOP IT ALL OFF,
WELL, HE PUTS IN
A TOP-NOTCH BURGER JOINT
THAT IS ALL ABOUT
SIMPLE, FAST AND FRESH.
THIS IS BURGER ME.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT
THE "SIMPLE,"
'CAUSE THAT'S
A PRETTY BIG BURGER.
ONE ITALIAN STALLION.
FAST FOR SURE,
AND DEFINITELY FRESH.
ORGANIC AND LOCAL
INGREDIENTS.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN ORIGINAL PLACE LIKE THIS.
THANKS TO LOCAL RESTAURATEUR
MARK ESTEE...
BURGER ON WHEAT.
WHO LUCKED INTO THIS PLACE.
I WORK FOR A NONPROFIT,
AND WE WERE LOOKING
FOR A PRESENCE
IN DOWNTOWN TRUCKEE.
THIS HAS A HUMUNGOUS
REFRIGERATOR, PLENTY OF STORAGE.
AND ROOM FOR A BURGER JOINT.
HEY, GUYS,
HOW ARE YOU?
NOW HE AND BUDDY TOM FARINA...
HERE YOU GO.
ARE CRANKIN' OUT BURGERS
DONE RIGHT.
ORDER COMES IN.
BURGER GOES ON.
FRESH TO ORDER, YEP.
FROM THE CAPRESE...
WITH FRESH VEGETABLES.
TO THE BARBECUE BISON...
CAN'T BEAT IT.
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
AN ITALIAN STALLION.
THIS IS A DOOZY.
WHERE BURGER
MEETS DELI SANDWICH.
PERFECT COMBINATION.
WHAT ARE WE
JUMPIN' INTO?
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A CABERNET VINAIGRETTE
FOR THE ITALIAN STALLION.
I LOVE THE NAME
ITALIAN STALLION.
YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
SO WE ADD CABERNET VINEGAR,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SOME FRESH DICED SHALLOTS,
KOSHER SALT AND BLACK PEPPER.
AND THEN WE JUST WHISK
ALL THAT TOGETHER.
WHAT'S THIS GOING ON?
THE ITALIAN STALLION--
IT'S GOT FRESH MORTADELLA.
WE SLICE IT UP
WITH SOME GENOA SALAMI.
SLICE IT UP.
NOW THE DANGER--THERE NEEDS
TO BE A GUARD WALKING WITH US
WHEN WE COME BACK
FROM THE SLICING.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S FLAMING UP.
NO, IT'S NOT. STEAM.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A BISON BURGER ON,
SALT AND A LITTLE PEPPER.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN BISON
TO PEOPLE?
BASICALLY IT'S JUST GOT
A STRONGER BEEF FLAVOR.
IT'S LEANER.
THIS IS ALL FREE-RANGE BISON.
SO THE BUN'S DOWN,
BURGER COOKS.
LITTLE JUICE TO THE TOP,
IS THAT WHEN YOU FLIP?
THAT'S WHEN WE'RE READY.
THOSE BUNS ARE DYNAMITE.
YEAH. FANTASTIC.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME PROVOLONE
CHEESE TO THAT BISON BURGER.
LET THAT MELT
FOR A SECOND.
I'M JUST GONNA ADD THAT
TO THAT.
ADD OUR SALAMI,
OUR MORTADELLA ON TOP OF THAT,
LETTUCE, TOMATO, PICKLE,
THE HOT CHOPPED PEPPERS...
MMM.
AND THEN WE'LL JUST ADD
THE CABERNET VINAIGRETTE.
THERE'S NOTHING ABOUT THAT
I DON'T LIKE.
IS THIS A BIG HIT
AROUND HERE?
BIG HIT, YEAH.
OH, GOSH,
LOOK AT THAT THING.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DO
THE HUNCH?
THE HUNCH OVER?
YEAH. HAVE YOU EVER SEEN IT?
GRAB YOUR PLATE.
OKAY.
WHEN YOU BRING THIS UP,
YOU GOT TO GET YOUR ELBOWS
ABOVE YOUR WRISTS
SO YOU DON'T HAVE THE GREASE
DRIP DOWN INTO YOUR PITS.
(laughs)
READY? TWO. THREE.
DO I HAVE ANYTHING HERE?
NO?
NO, YOU'RE GOOD.
THAT'S WHY IT'S COOL. OKAY.
THAT'S DELICIOUS, MAN.
SO YOU GET
THE HOT OF THE BURGER,
THE HOT CHILI PEPPER
BUT RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE,
CHAMPIONSHIP COLD CUTS.
IT'S ALL THE FAVORITE THINGS
I WANT IN A DELI SANDWICH
MIXED WITH A BURGER.
THANK YOU.
REALLY LIKE IT.
ALL RIGHT,
I GOT AN ITALIAN STALLION.
THE ITALIAN MEATS
AND THE SWEET AND HOT PEPPERS...
OH, HOT PEPPERS.
THERE YOU GO,
HOT PEPPERS.
KEEPS YOU COMING BACK
FOR ANOTHER BITE.
PRETTY MUCH ANY KIND OF BURGER
YOU WANT YOU'RE GONNA GET.
TURKEY BURGER WITH CHEDDAR
COMING OFF.
AHI TUNA BURGERS,
THEY'VE GOT VEGGIE BURGERS.
I GOT THE DIRTY BIRD.
AWESOME BURGER.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
THAT'S CHICKEN ALL DAY,
NICE AND FRESH.
AND THEY'LL MAKE
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
IF I WANT CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
I CAN HAVE CARAMELIZED ONIONS?
(Tom) YES, YOU CAN.
CHEDDAR CHEESE, PEPPER JACK,
SWISS, BLEU CHEESE,
AVOCADO...
AVOCADO.
AND A FRIED EGG.
WE'LL PUT A FRIED EGG
ON ANYTHING.
YEAH, LIKE THIS ONE...
THE TRUCKEE TRAINWRECK--
OH, IT'S A DELICIOUS BURGER.
IT'S GOT ONION RINGS
AND TURKEY CHILI, THAT'S BOMBER.
THE CHILI HAS
PEANUT BUTTER IN IT,
SO IT'S GOT
A UNIQUE FLAVOR TO IT.
SERIOUSLY PEANUT BUTTER'S
GONNA GO IN THE CHILI?
YEAH.
NO, WE'RE NOT.
SERIOUSLY?
OKAY, SO WE START OUT
WITH SOME BROWNED TURKEY.
GRIDDLE THIS UP,
ADD A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
JUST GET IT SLIGHTLY BROWNED.
SCOOP THAT INTO THE POT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
SOME RED KIDNEY BEANS...
OKAY.
OKAY, BLACK BEANS,
PINTO BEANS...
GREEN CHILIES.
CHILI SAUCE,
ONION POWDER,
SOME GARLIC POWDER,
CHILI POWDER.
THEN WE DO SHOTS
OF WORCESTERSHIRE.
SOME WATER.
THERE WE GO.
AND STIR.
AND SOME SALT
AND PEPPER.
LET IT SIMMER
FOR THREE HOURS.
CHILI'S GOOD TO GO.
LOOKS GREAT.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
PEANUT BUTTER,
WHICH IS THE SPECIAL INGREDIENT
TO THE CHILI.
STIR THAT UP.
WHOSE IDEA WAS THIS?
PHEW. THIS CHILI'S READY?
YEAH.
I'LL JUST LADLE A LITTLE.
GOT A SPOON?
YEAH.
IT WORKS.
IT'S A LOT
OF WELL-ROUNDED FLAVOR.
I MIGHT HAVE BEEN HARD-PRESSED
TO PICK PEANUT BUTTER OUT.
NO, I DIDN'T LIKE IT.
SO OUR CHILI'S DONE.
NOW WE MAKE
THE TRUCKEE TRAINWRECK.
OKAY.
START WITH THE BURGER--
80-20, MEYER BEEF, ALL NATURAL.
LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DIP
OUR ONION RINGS.
WE USE TEMPURA BATTER.
NICE, SUPER ICE-COLD BATTER.
WOW, IT'S THICK
LIKE ICE CREAM.
WE'LL LET THOSE
FRY UP.
AND THEN WE'LL GRIDDLE
OUR BUN AND A FRIED EGG.
NO FRIED EGG FOR ME,
REALLY TRYING TO CUT DOWN.
ONION RINGS DONE?
ONION RINGS ARE THERE.
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKING
TEMPURA BATTER.
SO THIS BUN IS GRIDDLED.
ADD A LITTLE SEASONING SAUCE
TO THAT--WE MAKE IT IN-HOUSE--
LETTUCE, TOMATO, PICKLE.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE BURGER
OFF AND PUT IT ON THE FLATTOP.
GET SOME OF OUR TURKEY CHILI.
ON THE FLATTOP WE DO IT,
NOT ON THE BUN.
THERE YOU GO.
CHEDDAR CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE ONION RING
ON TOP OF THAT.
DOME IT, LID IT, ANYTHING?
CHEESE MELTER.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT
OUT OF THERE, RIGHT THERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD A LITTLE
CHILI RIGHT IN THE ONION RING.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHAT IDIOT'S GONNA BITE
INTO THAT HOT MESS?
I JUST WANT YOU TO SEE
THIS MONSTROSITY.
MMM. THAT'S
AN ALL-AMERICAN BURGER.
THE TOMATO'S NICE.
PICKLE'S IN THERE.
BURGER'S COOKED
THE RIGHT WAY.
DON'T PICK UP TOO MUCH
OF THE PEANUT BUTTER.
THAT WOULD BE ONE I WOULD
DEFINITELY ORDER AGAIN. MMM.
NICE JOB.
I GOT THE TRUCKEE TRAINWRECK.
DELICIOUS.
I GOT THE RINGS
FOR THE TRAINWRECK ON.
(man) IT'S GOT THE CRUNCH
FROM THE ONION RING,
WHICH IS AWESOME.
YOU GET THAT LITTLE CHILI
SURPRISE RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
THE FRIED IN THERE,
IT'S QUITE A MOUTHFUL.
THE TRUCKEE TRAINWRECK.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE ABOUT IT?
IT TASTES GOOD
AND HAS A LOT OF STUFF ON IT.
HE KNOWS.
GOT AN ITALIAN STALLION.
SIMPLE, FAST AND FRESH.
JUST A COOL PLACE.
THIS IS ABOUT ONE
OF THE MOST PICTURESQUE
BURGER JOINTS YOU CAN SEE
AND A LOT OF GREAT PEOPLE.
A LOT OF GREAT PEOPLE,
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
IT'S ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE WITH ME.
JORDAN, I GOT A TRAINWRECK
COMING IN
AND A DIRTY BIRD
COMING OFF RIGHT NOW.
IT'S NOTHING WITHOUT THEM
AND OUR PRODUCTS.
THAT'S REALLY WHAT
WE'RE ABOUT.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF, MAN.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS, MAN.
AWESOME TIME.
UP NEXT...
STEVE MARTIN ON.
WE'RE HEADING TO KANSAS CITY...
IT'S THE BEST FOOD
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
FOR, YEAH, BATTERED BURGERS.
THAT'S A LOT
OF FLAVOR, MAN.
I'M HERE ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF KANSAS CITY
IN AN AREA KNOWN AS WALDO.
NOW IT'S ABOUT 5 MILES SOUTH
OF THE PLAZA,
AND I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S OWNED BY TWO BROTHERS.
NOW ONE OF THE BROTHERS COMES
FROM THE ELECTRONICS INDUSTRY,
AND THE OTHER BROTHER, EXACTLY,
HE OWNS A TATTOO PARLOR.
SO THEY ALWAYS WANTED TO HAVE
A RESTAURANT TOGETHER,
AND THIS IS IT.
THIS IS SWAGGER.
(speaking indistinctly)
(man) YES, PLEASE.
PULLED PORK, A DEAD TEXAN,
READY TO GO.
AND YOU GUYS HAVE NEVER OWNED
RESTAURANTS BEFORE?
(both) NO.
BUT FOR BROTHERS
DEREK BOONE...
HEY, DUSTIN, WE'RE GOOD.
AND DUSTIN CRAIGHEAD...
STEVE MARTIN ON.
IGNORANCE WAS BLISS.
HOT.
WE JUST DOVE HEAD FIRST.
THROW CAUTION TO THE WIND.
THAT'S NOT HOW
IT'S SUPPOSED TO WORK GENERALLY.
NO.
BUT IT DID.
HERE YOU GO, GEORGE.
WE APPROACH THINGS WITH
THE SAME KIND OF ZEAL.
AND THANKFULLY,
A TRAINED CHEF...
GOT AN ORDER UP
ON A STEVE MARTIN.
JERRY FORNESS.
SOMEONE GOT THE SAMURAI,
DUDE.
WHERE'D YOU FIND JERRY?
THROUGH THE TATTOO SHOP.
GOT THE FIDEL READY.
GETTING SOME INK, AND THEY SAID,
"YOU WANT TO RUN A KITCHEN?"
YEAH.
YOU CAN COME HERE
AND GET SOMETHING
THAT'S NOT YOUR EVERYDAY.
FROM THE HOT WINGS...
AFTER WORK WE LOVE
TO HAVE THEIR HOT WINGS.
TO LOADED CHILI CHEESE FRIES...
THEIR FRESH CUT FRIES
ARE AMAZING.
(Jerry) BACHI BURGERS
GOING DOWN.
EVEN A BURGER THAT'S BATTERED
AND DEEP-FRIED.
SURIBACHI'S VERY UNIQUE.
IT'S TEMPURA BATTERED AND THIS
REALLY GOOD WASABI COLESLAW,
REALLY GOOD.
HOW ARE WE GONNA DO THIS?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE TEMPURA BATTER.
SO THIS IS RICE FLOUR...
AND SALT.
CAKE FLOUR AND A LITTLE BIT
OF LEAVENING AGENT.
TAKE SOME COLD WATER
AND MIX IT TOGETHER
LIKE A THICK PANCAKE BATTER.
THE KEY
IS SUPER COLD WATER
SO IT REALLY MAKES IT
ADHERE TO STUFF.
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
THAT SHOULD ABOUT DO IT.
WE'LL MAKE THE HAMBURGER.
WE DO THIS BY HAND AND KIND OF
PATTY IT OUT. PRESS IT DOWN.
SEASON IT WITH SALT
AND PEPPER,
A LITTLE GRANULATED GARLIC,
ONION.
OKAY, SOME AQUA NET.
A LITTLE AQUA NET.
THROW THAT DOWN.
WE GRILL IT TO
THE TEMPERATURE YOU WANT IT,
THEN WE LET IT SET AND REST
SO THE JUICES
DON'T COME FLOWING OUT.
FLOWING OUT OF IT, RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE WASABI
MAYO FOR THE COLESLAW.
TWO WHOLE EGGS,
TABLESPOON OF GARLIC.
GO BIG.
GO BIG. TEARING IT UP.
YOU'RE AN ANIMAL.
OH, THERE YOU GO.
WASABI.
GENEROUS.
COME ON BY. WE'LL REPAIR THE TOP
OF YOUR HEAD AFTER...
WE GOT A RED WINE VINEGAR,
DIJON MUSTARD...
THAT'S AN EMULSIFIER THERE.
POWDERED SUGAR.
HOW MUCH
ARE YOU PUTTING IN?
QUITE A BIT.
THIS IS GETTING MORE INTERESTING
AS WE GO ON.
WE TAKE SOME
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
(whistles)
SMELL THAT WASABI COMING OUT
OF THERE, BIG-TIME.
DO YOU WANT TO TASTE IT?
REALLY GOOD.
THE SUGAR'S
AN INTERESTING COMPONENT.
THE BITE OF THE VINEGAR,
I CAN FEEL IT RIGHT THERE.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THAT
WITH THE SLAW?
YEP.
IT'S A PRETTY THICK
CUT THERE.
WE GO PRETTY RUSTIC
AROUND HERE.
POUR SOME IN THE SLAW.
SOME BLACK SESAME SEEDS
AND WHITE SESAME SEEDS, TOASTED.
DIG IT.
GREEN ONIONS,
AND WE'LL JUST MIX IT AROUND.
SET IT UP
SO IT STAYS TOGETHER.
STILL HAVE A LITTLE CRUNCH
OF THE CABBAGE.
LOOKS GREAT.
CAN'T WAIT TO TRY THIS.
TAKE THE BURGER AND DIP IT
IN THE FLOUR.
THEN WE'LL DIP IT
IN THE TEMPURA BATTER.
LITTLE FLOUR
TO STICK TO THE MEAT,
TEMPURA BATTER
STICKS TO THE FLOUR.
TAKE IT OVER TO THE FRYER.
THROW IT RIGHT IN THERE.
WHAT TEMP WE RUNNING
THAT FRYER AT?
350. FLIP THIS OVER.
BUTTER THE BUN AND THROW IT
IN THE PANINI MACHINE.
THAT'S YOUR BUN TOASTER?
YEAH. TAKE THE BOTTOM OF THE
BUN, PUT ON HOT ASIAN MUSTARD.
THAT MUCH?
LET IT KNOW IT'S THERE.
SRIRACHA SAUCE.
TAKE THIS OUT.
IS THIS UNDER
THE "LIGHT AND HEALTHY"
PART OF THE MENU?
(laughs)
TAKE SOME PEPPER JACK.
COLESLAW, BIG HANDFUL,
THROW IT ON THERE.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S A LOT OF BURGER.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
WHOA.
I GOT THE MUSTARD ON THE BOTTOM.
OOH. SLAW'S GOT
A NICE CRUNCH TO IT.
THE BURGER'S COOKED TO TEMP.
TEMPURA'S NICE AND CRISPY.
THAT'S A LOT OF FLAVOR, MAN.
I LIKE THAT. THAT'S PACKING IT.
NICE JOB.
OH, THANKS, MAN.
SURIBACHI.
THE CRUNCH ON THE BATTER
IS PROBABLY MY FAVORITE.
IT HAS A LITTLE KICK TO IT,
DEFINITELY WANT TO HAVE YOUR
BEER HANDY OR SOME WATER HANDY.
MAKES ME DO THE FOOD DANCE.
(laughs)
KENTUCKY COLONEL.
YOU DON'T COME TO A BAR
AND EXPECT TO HAVE FOOD
LIKE THIS.
IT'S SO DIFFERENT AND UNIQUE.
I LIKE THE CUBAN BECAUSE
HE DOES IT A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
HE SMOKES PORK SHOULDER.
ANYWHERE FROM 16 TO 20 HOURS,
DEPENDING ON THE TEMPERATURE.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
I KEEP COMING BACK TO THE PULLED
PORK BECAUSE IT'S THAT GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE
ABOUT THE CHILI?
IT'S MADE WITH BEER.
I'M A BEER GUY.
THIS IS PRETTY MUCH,
LIKE, ALL BEER.
THAT GALLON OF BEER'S
GONNA GO IN THERE?
YEAH.
SERIOUSLY?
MMM. THAT'S A MEAL
RIGHT THERE, DUDE.
AHI TUNA CLUB.
THEY BRING SOMETHING SPECIAL
AND ORIGINAL
TO EVERY PLATE THEY DO HERE.
LIKE A BURGER STUCK
IN THE MIDDLE
OF TWO GRILLED CHEESE
SANDWICHES.
THE DEAD TEXAN.
DEAD TEXAN.
HE SAID DEAD TEXAN.
TAKE SOME GROUND BEEF,
MAKE A BURGER.
AND THIS ONE WE KIND OF
GO FLATTER.
AS OPPOSED TO TRIANGULAR.
OR AN OCTAGON.
LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC
AND GRANULATED ONION.
YOU'RE LIBERAL WITH THAT.
IT'S NOT A BREADING, RIGHT?
(laughs) NO.
JUST CHECKING.
LITTLE AQUA NET.
ONCE AGAIN
FOR THE BIG HAIR.
NEVER STOPS BEING FUNNY
IN MY BOOK.
SO WE'RE GONNA COOK UP
THE BURGER.
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE GRILLED CHEESE?
THE BREAD WE USE
FOR THIS BURGER
IS TWO GRILLED CHEESE
SANDWICHES.
LIKE THIS?
YEAH.
THAT'S GONNA GO
INSIDE OF IT?
YEAH.
YOU GUYS HAVE A SMALL FORKLIFT
TO GET ME IN MY CAR?
WE GOT A WHEELBARROW.
SOME JALAPEÑOS.
OH, BOY, RAW.
JUST REALLY LIKE TO GET
THAT SHARP CRUNCH AND BITE.
YEAH.
THAT'LL BE GENTLE.
THREE SLICES OF BACON.
I'M SURPRISED
YOU EVEN COOK THE BACON.
BUTTER IT DOWN, DON'T WANT
TO LEAVE OUT THE FAT.
THAT'S GONNA GO
TO THE SANDWICH EXPRESS.
PRESS THAT DOWN.
THERE'S MORE TO THIS?
IT GETS A FRIED EGG ON IT.
OH, OF COURSE IT DOES.
SOME CHEDDAR CHEESE
ON THE BURGER.
THE RAW JALAPEÑO
GRILLED CHEESE IS READY.
WHAT ARE YOU PUTTING ON THERE?
PEPPERCORN MAYO
THAT WE MAKE IN-HOUSE.
THROW THE BURGER DOWN,
EGG...
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
SOME TOMATOES AND SOME ONIONS,
SOME LETTUCE.
AND THEN DRIVE IT
WITH A RAILROAD TIE.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
TWO GRILLED CHEESE, A BURGER,
A FRIED EGG. (whistles)
I UNDERSTAND WHY IT'S CALLED
THE DEAD TEXAN NOW.
OH, I JUST GOT
THE RAW JALAPEÑO.
MMM. NOW I'VE MOVED
INTO THE PEPPERCORN MAYO.
VERY TASTY.
LITTLE KISS OF SOME BACON.
THAT'S CRAZY.
CAN ANYBODY REALLY EAT THIS?
OH, YEAH.
OKAY. SO THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
IT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
I GOT NOTHING TO SAY,
BUT GET ME IN THE CAR.
LOOK AT THAT. DEFINITELY DON'T
FIND THAT SOMEWHERE ELSE.
AND THE PEPPERCORN MAYO,
GANGSTER.
WE HAVE THE DEAD TEXAN.
A LITTLE KICK TO IT
BUT NOT TOO CRAZY.
BEST SANDWICH
THEY SERVE HERE.
REALLY?
TAKES A LOT OF BEERS
TO GET IT DOWN, THOUGH.
YEAH, IT DOES.
I GOT A FIDEL CASTRO.
(man) THEY BRING SOMETHING
DIFFERENT TO THE TABLE.
GOT AN ORDER UP
ON A WALDO TRUCKER.
IT'S THE BEST FOOD
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I EAT HERE
EVERY CHANCE I GET.
GREAT HOME AWAY FROM HOME
FOR PEOPLE.
IT'S GOT ALL THE COMPONENTS.
CONGRATULATIONS, GUYS.
YEAH.
NICE TO MEET YA.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
THANKS FOR COMING.
APPRECIATE IT.
NEXT STOP...
DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HEADING TO NASHVILLE...
(man) LAMB BURGER'S UP.
WHERE IT'S ALL IN THE MIX.
THE LOVE SPICE?
THAT'S LOVE.
CALL IT LOVE SPICES,
CALL IT SEVEN SPICES,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
SO HERE I AM IN NASHVILLE,
MY GO-TO TOWN
WHEN I ROLL IN FOR
THE JACK DANIEL'S INVITATIONAL
BARBECUE COMPETITION
OVER IN LYNCHBURG.
NOW WHEN I SAY "NASHVILLE,"
WHAT KIND OF FOOD YOU THINKING?
EXACTLY. GREAT AMERICAN FOOD.
BUT WHEN I PUT A LITTLE
TRIPLE "D" SPIN ON THINGS,
WHAT DO YOU GET?
YOU KNOW IT, GREAT AMERICAN
AND GREEK CUISINE.
THIS IS
ATHENS FAMILY RESTAURANT.
BACON LAMB BURGER'S UP.
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
MOUSAKA.
THE FOOD HERE
IS JUST INCREDIBLE.
(woman) SUZUKAKIA.
AUTHENTIC GREEK
TO THE DINER-TYPE FOOD.
TODAY I HAD A B.L.T.
MY VERY FAVORITE
IS THE SPANAKOPITA.
ALL CRANKED OUT BY
CHEF ADEL ELOSTTA...
PICK UP.
AND CO-OWNER MUHAMMAD RASRAS.
(Adel) MY PHILOSOPHY
HERE IN THE RESTAURANT
IS TO MAKE SURE THIS FOOD IS
THE BEST QUALITY FOR THE MONEY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE DOES DO IT
TO MAKE IT AS GOOD AS IT IS.
TREATS FOOD WITH
A LOT OF RESPECT.
YOU WANT TO ADD
SOME LOVE TO YOUR FOOD.
LITERALLY.
THIS IS THE LOVE SPICE?
CALL IT LOVE SPICE,
CALL IT SEVEN SPICES,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
NO, LOVE SPICE IS WAY
MORE MARKETABLE.
SO THE TOASTED CUMIN IS
THE FIRST THING FOR LOVE SPICE.
SMELLS GREAT.
AND THEN THE GREEN CARDAMOM--
I LOVE TO COOK WITH CARDAMOM...
CORIANDER SEEDS.
WHOLE BLACK PEPPER,
SOME OF THIS.
CLOVES.
WHOA, GENEROUS.
TURKISH BAY LEAF.
MM-HMM.
AND KNOW WHAT MISTIKA IS?
MIDEAST MYSTIQUE.
CAN I TASTE IT?
TASTE IT.
(laughs)
WHAT IN THE WORLD?
THAT'S A SECRET.
GRIND EVERYBODY UP.
(whistles)
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE ONTO?
LAMB BURGER,
FROM EVERY PART OF THE LAMB.
THE BEST OF EACH.
WE CHOP IT ALL UP, OKAY.
DUMP IT ALL IN HERE.
THAT'S IT?
WE'LL GRIND IT.
LOOK AT HOW NICE
AND RED THAT IS.
NOW LET'S MAKE THE BURGER.
A LITTLE BIT OF KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, LOVE SPICE.
THE PANKO'S GONNA WORK
AS THE BINDER,
'CAUSE THE LAMB JUST DOESN'T
HAVE ENOUGH FAT.
TO HOLD IT TOGETHER, YEAH.
SCOOP THIS 4 OUNCE,
ANOTHER 4 OUNCE.
TWO PATTIES,
PUT IT TOGETHER.
MAKE IT TO ONE.
WHY DON'T WE JUST GET
A BIGGER SCOOP?
WELL, I DON'T HAVE
A BIGGER SCOOP.
YOU WANT ONE
FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY?
SURE.
SO WE MAKE ALL THESE UP
AND THEN...
WE'LL GO TO THE GRILL.
SO WHAT GOES DOWN FIRST?
THE BACON.
THEN ONCE I HAVE IT
COOKED HALFWAY AT LEAST,
I PUT THE BURGER
ON THE FLATTOP.
MAKES IT SEAR.
FLIP THIS BACON OVER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA FORTIFY IT
WITH SOME FAT
INTO THAT LEAN LAMB.
NOW WE PUT SOME
OF THE CHARBROIL.
YES. AND WE'LL COVER IT.
WOW. THIS IS LIKE
A MEDIEVAL SHRINER'S.
WE'RE GONNA TOAST OUR BUN.
WE'RE GONNA FLIP OUR BURGER.
GONNA PUT THE SWISS CHEESE
ON TOP OF IT.
THEN THE BUN HERE, A LITTLE BIT
OF THOUSAND ISLAND.
AND YOU MAKE THAT?
YES.
ONION, LETTUCE AND ROMA TOMATO.
READY TO GO?
THAT'S A BIG BURGER.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
THERE WE GO.
SERVED WITH FRIES.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT IS SO GOOD.
I TASTE THE BACON FAT
AND THE SALT,
BUT THEN YOU GET INTO
THE DEPTH OF SPICE IN THERE.
MMM. IT'S THE LOVE SPICE.
WHEN YOU SAY GREAT AMERICAN
AND GREEK CUISINE TOGETHER,
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT THAT IS.
IT'S A GREAT BURGER.
(Adel) LAMB BURGER IS UP.
IT HAS WONDERFUL FLAVORS.
IT'S JUICY AND DELICIOUS.
YOUR MOUSAKA.
I'VE HAD A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYTHING. IT'S INCREDIBLE.
KOTOPITA IS UP.
YOU'RE IN BARBECUE COUNTRY,
BUT INSTEAD OF DOING THAT,
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA DO GREEK.
YOU DO WHAT YOU DO BEST.
I GOT TWO PASTICHIO UP.
FOLKS DEFINITELY ENJOY
GOOD COMFORT FOOD.
YEAH.
LIKE THE GREEK ANSWER
TO MEATBALLS.
SUZUKAKIA.
"SUZUK" IS MEATBALL.
YEAH.
LEARNIN' SOME GREEK
RIGHT HERE.
THAT WAS GREEK, RIGHT?
YES.
GOOD.
STRIP LOIN, CHOICE?
CHOICE.
CUT IT INTO CUBES, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA GRIND IT?
THERE YOU GO.
YOU JUST TOOK A NEW YORK STEAK
AND GROUND IT UP.
DON'T BE SORRY FOR THE SIRLOIN
BECAUSE YOU WILL TASTE IT.
I'M NOT SAD.
NOW WE'LL SEASON THE MEAT--
KOSHER SALT, NUTMEG...
LOVE SPICE?
LOVE SPICE.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT.
CHICKEN BASE.
GRATED ONION.
WITH THE JUICE.
SOME PARMESAN CHEESE.
I LIKE PARMESAN, THE SALTINESS
AND THE NUTTY FLAVOR.
WE'RE NUTTY.
THERE WE GO.
(laughs)
RED WINE VINEGAR,
SOME PANKO.
YOU GOT ITALIAN IN THERE,
GREEK AND JAPANESE.
I WANT TO BRING IT OUT
THE BEST WAY POSSIBLE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT
LIKE 5 OUNCE.
MAKE IT LIKE A FOOTBALL.
THAT'S NOT A FOOTBALL.
THAT IS A LAWN DART.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
DRIZZLE SOME BUTTER ON IT.
HOW LONG ARE
WE GONNA COOK THIS?
45 MINUTES, 250 DEGREES.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO?
SUZUKAKIA SAUCE.
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER...
POUND OF IT.
ONION, GARLIC...
(whistles)
BAY LEAVES
AND CORIANDER SEEDS,
WHOLE PEPPERCORN.
VERY IMPORTANT FOR THIS
CORIANDER TO BE TOASTED.
TO OPEN UP ITS FLAVOR.
YEAH.
SAME THING
WITH THE PEPPERCORN.
TOMATO PASTE.
STIR THIS UP.
I ADD MY FLOUR.
THAT'S GONNA TIGHTEN IT UP.
LITTLE BIT OF WHITE WINE.
ADD WATER.
ADD THE CHICKEN BASE.
HOW LONG'S THIS
GONNA COOK DOWN?
ONE HOUR.
THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT?
STRAIN IT.
ARE THESE READY?
YEAH.
(whistles)
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
AND DUMP IT IN THE SAUCE.
OH, EVERYBODY
GOES IN THE POOL.
YEAH. LITTLE RICE, GREEN BEANS
SAUTéED IN LIGHT TOMATO SAUCE.
AND THAT'S HOW
WE SERVE IT UP.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF PARMESAN
CHEESE RIGHT ON TOP OF IT.
ENJOY.
THAT IS SUPER TENDER.
ALL THE FLAVORS COMING OUT
OF THE LOVE SPICE,
AND THE SAUCE
COMPLEMENTS IT WELL
WITHOUT TAKING AWAY
THE FLAVOR.
YOU COME TO A GREAT AMERICAN
GREEK RESTAURANT,
THIS IS WHAT YOU'RE GONNA GET,
SUPER GREEK.
DIDN'T RICK JAMES DO
A SONG ABOUT SUPER GREEK?
OH, THAT WAS "SUPER FREAK."
I LIKE IT, MAN. GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
(woman) HERE'S
YOUR SUZUKAKIA.
WITH THE TOMATO SAUCE
IT'S JUST DIVINE.
(man) BIFTEKI'S READY.
YOU JUST CAN'T GO WRONG
IN HERE.
QUAIL.
(man) THEY'VE BEEN ABLE
TO INTRODUCE GREEK FOOD,
AND YET STILL OFFER PEOPLE
AMERICAN FOOD.
SOMETIMES IN THE SAME DISH.
KOTOPITA.
A GREEK POTPIE.
GREEK POTPIE?
AND LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
KNOCKED IT OUT
WITH THE PHYLLO.
HOW IS EVERYONE?
ATHENS FAMILY RESTAURANT
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE,
IS A GREEK DINER...
HERE'S YOUR SUZUKAKIA.
FOR THE LOCAL CROWD...
IT'S JUST REALLY A FAMILY
DOWN-HOME KIND OF PLACE.
WHERE CHEF ADEL ELOSTTA...
CHEESE PIE.
IS PUTTING AMERICAN AND GREEK
COMFORT FOOD TOGETHER.
(woman) KOTOPITA.
(man) IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A CHICKEN POTPIE,
EXCEPT IT'S A PHYLLO DOUGH,
SO IT'S KIND OF FLAKY.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO, BOSS?
WE'RE ABOUT TO MAKE KOTOPITA.
KOTO IS A CHICKEN.
KOTO. OKAY.
PITA...
LIKE PITA BREAD. OKAY.
CHICKEN PITA.
YEAH, KOTOPITA.
AH, HOW MANY TIMES ON TRIPLE "D"
HAVE WE SHOT GREEK JOINTS,
NO ONE'S EVER
BROKE IT DOWN FOR ME.
NICE JOB.
YOU'RE THE TEACHER.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL MAKE THE CHICKEN
PIE MIX FIRST.
WE'LL START
WITH SOME BUTTER.
CHICKEN BREAST.
CUT IN CUBES.
ALL RIGHT.
GONNA BROWN THIS?
GONNA LET IT SIT
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
AND I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF DILL...
FRESH DILL.
SOME CHOPPED ONIONS,
CHOPPED GARLIC,
LITTLE BIT OF KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, CARROTS.
LOT OF CARROTS
IN GREEK FOOD?
WE EAT A LOT OF CARROTS.
CELERY, SOME CHICKEN BASE.
COOK THIS DOWN.
I LET IT SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
AND THEN WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO WITH THIS?
STRAIN OUT
ANY EXTRA JUICES.
'CAUSE IF YOU GET
THAT PHYLLO DOUGH WET...
YEAH.
YOU'RE DONE.
WE'RE ABOUT TO MAKE
THE BéCHAMEL SAUCE.
TRADITIONAL BéCHAMEL.
SOME MILK, BRING IT
TO A BOILING POINT.
SIT THIS BACK HERE.
SOME BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A ROUX.
WE ADD THE FLOUR
TO THE BUTTER.
EQUAL PARTS FAT
AND FLOUR.
YES.
OKAY, AND THEN NOW...
THE MILK UP TO
THE BOILING POINT.
I ADD A LITTLE BIT AT A TIME.
IT'S ENOUGH FOR NOW.
THERE WE GO.
JUST ONE EGG.
YOU SEE HOW THE EGG
MAKES IT LOOK?
THAT'S TIGHT BéCHAMEL.
AND THAT'S GONNA MAKE US
THE...
KOTOPITA.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE REST OF THE MIXTURE.
YES.
LOOKS LIKE THE BEGINNING
OF CHICKEN POTPIE.
HERE WE GO.
PARMESAN CHEESE, FETA.
(whistles)
THE BéCHAMEL WE MADE,
BROUGHT TO YOU BY
SPACKLE AND SONS.
SOME EGGS.
A LITTLE EXTRA BINDER.
AND NOW YOU'RE GONNA GET
INTO IT.
THAT'S IT.
SO NOW WE GET THE PHYLLO.
BUTTER THE PHYLLO.
BIG NICE SCOOP
OF KOTOPITA MIX.
PRESS IT DOWN A LITTLE.
FLIP IT OVER.
GRACIOUS WITH THE BUTTER.
I LOVE BUTTER.
THE WAY YOU FOLD IT, YOU HAVE
THE EXTRA CRUST BUILT UP ON TOP.
IT BUILDS A NICE,
LIGHT, FLAKY CRUST,
KIND OF LIKE
A PIE SHELL CRUST.
THAT'S IT,
NICE LITTLE PIE.
SO WE JUST KEEP MAKING THESE,
BRUSH IT OUT.
AND HOW LONG ARE
WE GONNA COOK THIS?
40 MINUTES, 350 DEGREES.
LOOK AT THOSE.
(cracking)
OH, YOU CAN JUST HEAR THAT
PHYLLO DOUGH JUST CRACKING.
AND WHY ARE WE PUTTING IT
ON THE FLATTOP?
JUST TO GET RID OF
ANY EXTRA BUTTER.
THAT IT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN COOKING IN.
PUT IT WITH
A MINI GREEK SALAD.
THAT THING
IS CRUNCH-A-LICIOUS.
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S NOT CREAMY.
THIS IS LIKE A PASTY
BUT DONE WITH THE PHYLLO DOUGH.
THE LAYERS, THAT'S CRAZY.
IT WAS GREAT.
THAT'S EVERYWHERE IN GREECE.
REALLY?
EVERYWHERE.
YOU SEE IT IN THE BAKERY
LIKE A DOUGHNUT.
IN THE MORNING?
YEAH.
OH, SEE? THAT'S MY KIND
OF BREAKFAST.
KNOCKED IT OUT
WITH THE PHYLLO.
KOTOPITA.
IT'S CRUSTY, SAVORY
AND VERY TASTY.
SUZUKAKIA'S UP.
I LIKE EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
SPANAKOPITA.
NOT ONLY IS IT EXOTIC,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
LAMB KEBAB IS UP.
YOU'RE LIVING
THE AMERICAN DREAM, MAN.
ABSOLUTELY
IT'S COMING TRUE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TAKE OVER THE SHOW.
SEE YOU LATER. GOOD-BYE.
(laughs)
PUT THE SHADES ON THE BACK
OF THE HEAD. THERE YOU GO.
GOOD-BYE.
I NEED YOU.
TURN AROUND.
SHOW 'EM THE SHADES.
SHOW THE SHADES.