HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
PORKAPALOOZA.
WHOO!
IN NOLENSVILLE, TENNESSEE...
PORK SANDWICH WEARING SLAW.
THE BARBECUE JOINT...
(man) THERE'S NO COMPETITION.
THIS IS IT?
THIS IS IT.
WHERE THEY'RE GOING
WHOLE HOG...
YOU GOT TO EXPERIENCE
THIS PLACE.
AND DOING THEIR TAKE ON TACOS.
I GOT THREE REDNECK TACOS.
MMM. TOTALLY INGENIOUS.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
IN BELLEVUE, KENTUCKY...
SAUSAGE NAPOLEON.
THE LOCAL CAFé...
THE FOOD'S GREAT,
ALWAYS FRESH.
DOING CAJUN PORK...
WE'RE GONNA MAKE ANDOUILLE
AND THEN CASE IT.
FOR A CAJUN CLASSIC...
(woman) éTOUFFéE.
AND, OH, YEAH...
FROG LEGS.
JUST HOP ON OVER
AND TRY THIS.
AND IN
LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA...
PORK CHOP FOR YOU.
A JOINT
IN MY OLD STOMPING GROUNDS...
THE FOOD IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
WHERE KILLER COMFORT FOOD...
(man) TWO PORK CHOPS, MEDIUM.
MEANS STUFFING A TOP CHOP.
MMM. WAY TO GO.
MM-HMM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NICE JOB.
ALL RIGHTY.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP RIGHT HERE
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM ON TOUR,
THE TRIPLE "D" PORKAPALOOZA.
NOW I'M ABOUT 20 MILES SOUTHEAST
OF NASHVILLE IN NOLENSVILLE
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE OLD-SCHOOL, WHOLE-HOG,
LOW-AND-SLOW BARBECUE.
THIS IS
MARTIN'S BAR-B-QUE JOINT.
READY? WHOO!
IT'S THE WHOLE HOG.
THAT'S WHAT HE'S KNOWN FOR.
(man) THEY CLOSE THAT DOOR UP
RIGHT THERE,
AND THAT SMELL JUST
PERMEATES THE PLACE.
ALL RIGHT, PORK PLATE.
THE PULLED PORK MELTS IN
YOUR MOUTH. IT'S RIDICULOUS.
PORK SANDWICH WEARING SLAW.
IT'S ALL WOOD.
IT'S ALL NATURAL.
AND IT'S ALL DONE BY HAND
BY OWNER PATRICK MARTIN...
FIRE HER UP.
IN HIS CUSTOM-MADE SMOKER...
THROW THE LOGS ON TOP.
WOOD BREAKS DOWN TO SMALL COALS.
THEY FALL DOWN BELOW.
WE SCOOP 'EM OUT HERE.
WE OPEN THIS UP.
THROW YOUR BETTER COALS
UNDERNEATH OF THERE.
YEAH.
WOW.
FOR EVERYTHING
FROM CHICKEN AND TURKEY
TO RIBS AND BRISKET
TO A 200-POUND HOG.
204, TO BE EXACT.
AND IT ALL STARTS WITH
THE HOUSE-MADE RUB.
MAKIN' BIG HOSS RUB.
THIS IS OUR PRE-RUB
THAT WE PUT ON EVERYTHING--
RIBS, BRISKET, SHOULDERS,
HOG, WHATEVER.
GIVES IT
A REALLY GOOD BARK.
WE START WITH OUR BROWN SUGAR.
THIS IS OUR DRY GARLIC.
GARLIC POWDER
OR GRANULATED GARLIC?
GARLIC POWDER, WHATEVER.
WHATEVER.
IT'S YOUR COOKING SHOW, SO...
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
KOSHER SALT.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
IT JUST LOOKS LIKE THAT.
WE WANT TO MIX UP THESE
THREE LARGE INGREDIENTS FIRST
AND GET THAT BROWN SUGAR
MIXED IT REALLY WELL.
THEN WE ADD OUR PAPRIKA.
CHILI POWDER.
YEAH. CAYENNE, LEMON PEPPER,
ONION POWDER.
YOU GOT A GOOD AMOUNT
OF SALT IN THERE
AND A GOOD AMOUNT OF SEASONING
BUT NOTHING REALLY OVER-SPICY.
YOU JUST LIKE IT--
WE'RE NOT LOOKING
FOR ANYTHING
BUT AN END RESULT
OF A GOOD BARK.
OKAY.
NOW DRY MUSTARD...
YEP.
OUR CINNAMON, WHITE SUGAR,
GINGER, COARSE BLACK PEPPER.
I LIKE IT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS.
BIG SCOOP OF THIS,
HOW MUCH ARE WE GONNA NEED?
THAT'S ENOUGH TO DO TWO HOGS.
WE WON'T USE ALL THAT.
YOU'RE NOT PUTTING IT
ON THE SKIN.
YOU'RE JUST GETTING
THE CAVITY DOWN, AND THAT'S IT.
LET'S GO. I'LL SHOW YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
BRINGING THE BOWL?
YEAH. READY?
MANUAL LABOR.
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
YOU WANTED TO COME TO FIND
OLD-SCHOOL BARBECUE, DON'T YOU?
DON'T START. LET'S GO.
LET'S GO.
WHOO!
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, GET ON THE...
YEAH, STAND ON
THE CORNER.
THAT'S WHAT MY GLOBE
SKATEBOARD SHOES ARE FOR.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M GONNA SEASON IT?
YEP, WE'RE GONNA RUB
OUR RUB ON IT.
ONLY ON THE MEAT, THERE'S NO
SENSE IN GETTING IT ON THE SKIN.
IT'S NOT GONNA DO YOU
ANY GOOD.
GET A LITTLE SPOT
ON THE HAM DOWN THERE.
SO NOW SAL AND BEAU
ARE GONNA PUT EACH ONE
OF THESE LEGS OUT
RIGHT HERE.
ABOUT TIME
THEY DID SOMETHING.
I KNOW. WE'RE GONNA
ROLL IT OVER FACE SIDE DOWN
FOR ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
COME ON. GET IT OVER.
I'M GONNA LET YOU
CLOSE HER.
BYE-BYE, LITTLE SWINE.
SEE YOU, BESSIE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW YOU GOT TO
MAINTAIN IT, PAY ATTENTION...
YEAH.
KEEP FEEDING THE FIRE.
THEN AFTER FOUR HOURS
WE'RE GONNA POP THE LID,
ROLL IT OVER,
WE BASTE IT
WITH THAT TRUE CAROLINA-STYLE
VINEGAR-BASED SAUCE...
MOP IT IN.
SOPPING IT.
COOK IT
AT ABOUT 190 DEGREES.
AND YOU JUST LET THE PIT
DO THE WORK FOR YOU.
SO HOW LONG HAS
THIS HOG BEEN DOWN?
26 HOURS.
LONG TIME.
THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
LET'S DO IT.
HOLY HOG.
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA DO,
WE'RE GONNA RIGHT
UNDER THIS RIB CAGE.
I'M GONNA PULL THIS MIDDLE
OF THE MEAT OUT.
THAT'S KIND OF THE CAVIAR,
SO TO SPEAK, OF THE HOG.
LOOK AT THAT.
SHOW YOU HOW EASY
THAT BLADE BONE PULLS OUT.
THIS IS WHERE
THE BACON COMES FROM.
WHOA.
THERE'S THE BEGINNING OF HAM.
HERE'S SOME SHOULDER MEAT.
LOAD HER UP.
THERE YOU GO.
SO HOW ARE
WE GONNA EAT THIS?
WE'RE GONNA DO
THREE SLIDERS.
NICE ROLL.
WE GOT THREE DIFFERENT
SAUCES HERE.
WE'LL START WITH THE...
AND YOU GUYS ARE
ALSO BASTING WITH THAT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S JUST A GOOD SIMPLE SAUCE.
I'M A VINEGAR SAUCE-LIKING
PERSON, SO...
MMM. THE PORK IS BEYOND JUICY
AND MOIST AND FLAVORFUL,
NOT OVER-SMOKED...
YEAH.
A LITTLE SWEET, A LITTLE SPICE,
NOT TOO MUCH VINEGAR,
ALL THE RED
FROM THE CHILI.
THAT'S IT.
THIS IS OUR DEVIL'S NECTAR,
OUR HOT SAUCE WITH
SOME HABANERO IN IT.
THAT'S GOOD.
AND WHAT'S THE LAST ONE?
NOW IS OUR SWEET DIXIE,
AND IT'S TRUE SOUTHERN-STYLE
SAUCE FROM TENNESSEE.
MMM.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT SWEETNESS IN THERE,
GOT A LITTLE MORE SUGAR,
STILL GOT SOME OF THAT TANG.
I'LL TAKE 2 GALLONS OF THAT.
GIVE ME 14 POUNDS OF THIS.
THAT'S PRIME TIME, MAN.
GET 'EM A PULLED PORK PLATE.
VERY MOIST,
ALMOST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
PORK PLATE.
THERE'S NO COMPETITION.
THIS IS IT?
THIS IS IT.
YOU JUST DON'T FIND IT ANYWHERE
ELSE LIKE PAT DOES IT.
ANY OF IT.
EIGHT WINGS, ALABAMA WHITE.
DEFINITELY TOP-NOTCH.
JUMBO BRISKET SANDWICH.
DEFINITELY THE BEST
IN NASHVILLE. AMAZING.
HANDS DOWN THE BEST?
HANDS DOWN THE BEST.
BECAUSE IN A TOWN
THAT'S NOT KNOWN FOR BARBECUE,
THIS GUY...
FULL SLABS, SPARE RIBS.
HAS A REAL PASSION...
TRUE SOUTHERN BARBECUE.
PATRICK'S PUTTING US
ON THE MAP.
AND HE'S PICKED UP
ON WHAT THE LOCALS LOVE.
BARBECUE ON CORN BREAD--
IT'S A NASHVILLE TRADITION.
THAT PATRICK CALLS
A REDNECK TACO.
I GOT THREE REDNECK TACOS.
IT LOOKS LIKE A PANCAKE
WITH PULLED PORK AND SLAW
AND HOT SAUCE ON IT.
DON'T LET IT
SCARE YOU OFF.
REDNECK TACOS ARE AMAZING.
MADE WITH WHOLE SHOULDERS
AND SMOKED FOR 20 HOURS
WITH THAT BIG HOSS RUB.
AND WE'RE JUST PULLING IT
AS WE NEED IT.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH, IF YOU PRE-PULL IT,
PORK GOES SOUTH QUICK.
MMM.
THAT'S MASSIVE BARK.
THE SUGAR'S CARAMELIZED.
IT TURNS REALLY DARK.
AND THAT GIVES THE BALANCE
TO THE PORK
ON THE INSIDE WITH THE FAT.
OH, MY GOSH.
KEEPING THAT SKIN ON.
BROTHER, YOU HAVE GOT
SOME POSITIONS ON BARBECUE
THAT I JUST GOT--
I GOT TO TELL YOU I RESPECT.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A REDNECK TACO WITH IT,
BUT WE'VE GOT
TO CAPTURE...
SOME MAGIC NECTAR.
THAT'S RIGHT. THIS IS GONNA
GO IN OUR CORN BREAD BATTER,
WHICH IS THE BASE
FOR THE TACO.
I'M GONNA WHISK IF YOU'LL POUR.
START WITH THE BUTTERMILK.
OKAY. WE'RE A TEAM.
GIVE ME THE EGG.
EGG COMING IN.
PEPPER.
PEPPER. AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN.
PIG FAT--I JUST THINK THIS
IS THE BEST PART RIGHT HERE.
SO PANCAKE BATTER
CONSISTENCY.
YEAH. NOW WE JUST USE
1/3 OF A CUP.
COOK THAT BOTH SIDES.
BUTTER THE COOKED SIDE.
WE PLATE IT RIGHT THERE.
THEN WE GET SOME OF OUR
PULLED PORK, PUT OUR SLAW ON,
THEN OUR SWEET DIXIE SAUCE.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
I MEAN, I'M DOWN
WITH THE WHOLE IDEA.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
IT'S LIKE BREAKFAST PULLED PORK.
I JUST GOT TO GIVE YOU
THE RESPECT FIRST WITH THE SLAW,
NICE CRUNCH, NICE VINEGAR.
THE DIXIE SAUCE,
YOU GET THE SWEET
AND THE DEEP RICH FLAVOR
OF THE PORK.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF BALANCE.
THIS CORNMEAL CAKE--
NICE CRUST ON THAT.
GREAT IDEA.
TOTALLY INGENIOUS.
THANKS, MAN.
APPRECIATE IT.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
CRAZY.
REDNECK TACOS.
REALLY GOOD CORN BREAD WITH
THE SLAW ON TOP AND THE PORK.
REDNECK TACO FOR YOU GUYS
TO SHARE.
IT'S SECOND TO NONE
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE.
(Patrick) JUMBO
PORK SANDWICH.
THIS GUY'S LEGIT.
HE'S LEGIT.
I GOT A BRISKET PLATE.
IF YOU REALLY LIKE BARBECUE, YOU
GOT TO EXPERIENCE THIS PLACE.
...CHICKEN DINNER.
(man) OLD-SCHOOL STYLE,
SLOW AND RIGHT,
AND IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
THIS IS THE DEFINITION
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT BARBECUE
ON TRIPLE "D."
THIS IS THE HOUSE
OF BARBECUE, MAN.
THANKS, BUDDY.
APPRECIATE THAT.
UP NEXT
ON THE PORKAPALOOZA TOUR...
DOGGIE.
WE'RE HEADING TO KENTUCKY...
WORKING WITH
SOME PORK BUTT?
YES, SIR.
FOR THE OLD GRIND.
LOOK AT THAT NICE WHITE FAT
THAT'S COMING OUT OF THERE.
ABOUT A BLOCK THAT WAY
IS THE OHIO RIVER,
AND RIGHT ACROSS THAT RIVER
IS CINCINNATI,
BUT THIS HERE,
THIS IS BELLEVUE, KENTUCKY,
AND WE'RE ON FAIRFIELD AVENUE
TO VISIT A JOINT
WHERE THE CHEF IS ALL ABOUT
SCRATCH-MAKING FOOD,
AND YOU KNOW I LOVE THAT.
THIS IS VIRGILS CAFE.
SHRIMP CREOLE,
HOUSE-CURED SALMON.
THE FOOD'S GREAT,
ALWAYS FRESH.
REALLY, REALLY DELICIOUS.
(woman) BURGER WITH SWISS.
IT'S EVERYDAY COMFORT FOOD...
(man) TWO CHILIS.
TO THE FANCY STUFF.
SAUSAGE NAPOLEON.
DELICIOUS.
LAYERS AND LAYERS OF FLAVORS.
ALL THANKS TO
OWNER MATTHEW BUSCHLE...
THANK YOU, SIR.
WHO JUMPED INTO
THE RESTAURANT BIZ AT 19.
I GOT YOUR PASTAS.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WORK FOR
PEOPLE THAT KIND OF LET ME GO.
AND NOW HE'S LETTING IT GO...
FIRE IN THE CREOLE.
AT HIS OWN PLACE.
WE TRY TO COOK EVERYTHING
WE POSSIBLY CAN FROM SCRATCH.
HIS PASTRAMI
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
HE MAKES HIS OWN SAUSAGE.
HOUSE-MADE BREAKFAST SAUSAGE.
AND SCRATCH-MADE ANDOUILLE.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE ANDOUILLE
AND THEN CASE IT.
DON'T TELL ME WE'RE SMOKING IT,
'CAUSE IF YOU SAY WE'RE GONNA...
YEAH.
I CAN'T HANDLE THIS.
IT'LL END UP
IN THE SMOKER.
WORKING WITH SOME PORK BUTT?
YES, SIR.
GRIND IT UP.
LOOK AT THAT NICE WHITE FAT
THAT'S COMING OUT OF THERE.
OKAY, SO WE GOT A COARSE GROUND
ON THE PORK BUTT.
WE HAVE TO DO A SLURRY.
I ACTUALLY MIX ALL THE SPICES
INTO, UM...
TAKE ALL OF THIS, POP IT INTO
THIS WATER AND WINE MIXTURE.
IT'S BETTER CHANCE OF HAVING
A VERY NICE EQUAL DISTRIBUTION.
YEAH.
KOSHER SALT,
SMOKED PAPRIKA, SOME THYME,
BLACK PEPPER.
YOU HAVE TO
ON THE CAYENNE.
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
GARLIC, RED PEPPER,
PINK SALT--
IT'S A CURING SALT--
LITTLE BIT OF HEAVY CREAM--
THAT'LL HELP BIND.
OKAY.
WATER AND WINE.
WHITE WINE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF PINOT.
THE WHITE WINE
FROM THE PINOT
IS A LOT CRISPER,
A LOT CLEANER.
THAT'S HOW I WHISK, TOO,
THE TONG WHISK.
IT JUST GOES IN
OVER THE TOP.
ARE YOU GONNA LET THIS
MARINATE AT ALL?
PUT IT INTO SERVICE
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
LOAD HER UP.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
THIS IS WHERE
IT'S GONNA GET AWESOME.
ARE WE JUST GONNA DO THESE
IN WHOLE BIG LINKS?
YEAH, 'CAUSE
WE'RE GONNA CHOP 'EM UP.
WE CUT IN ABOUT 2-INCH CHUNKS.
ROLL IT UP.
PIERCE THIS A COUPLE TIMES,
LET SOME OF THE PRESSURE
OUT OF THIS.
WHERE'S THE SMOKER?
BEHIND YOU,
THAT TINY LITTLE BEAT-UP
PRESSURE SMOKER, YES, SIR.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS COMES OUT.
CHIPS GO RIGHT HERE.
LOOK AT THAT LITTLE
COOKER SPOON. WOW.
I GOT IT FOR 300 BUCKS.
OKAY, SO WE FILL HER UP.
YEAH.
WE'VE GOT HICKORY
AND MESQUITE.
MM-HMM.
THIS IS HOW I DECORATE
MY CHRISTMAS TREE,
BUT, BOY, DOES IT SURE
CAUSE TROUBLE WITH THE DOGS.
NOW IN?
YEAH, PLEASE.
GONNA LINE HER UP. BATTEN DOWN
THE HATCHES, CAPTAIN.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THEN HOW LONG
WILL IT SMOKE?
ONCE IT'S UP TO TEMP,
ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
15 MINUTES--THAT'S IT?
HERE, PROTECT YOURSELF.
OH! OH, DOGGIE.
I FEEL LIKE A CEREMONIAL NOISE
OF HORNS WOULD PLAY
AND MEN WOULD MARCH.
LOOK AT THE JUICE IN HERE.
WATCH THIS.
NICE EVEN DISBURSEMENT
OF THE SEASONING. MMM.
AND IT'S THE KEY INGREDIENT
IN THIS CAJUN CLASSIC.
éTOUFFéE.
AMAZING. I GET IT
ALMOST EVERY TIME I COME.
WHAT WE INTO, BOSS?
STARTING A ROUX
FOR THE éTOUFFéE,
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
REALLY HOT PAN.
A REALLY HOT PAN.
SOME FLOUR.
GONNA LET THIS
GAIN SOME COLOR?
YES.
IT'S LIKE PEANUT BUTTER.
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT.
WE GO CELERY, RED ONION,
MIXED BELL PEPPERS,
LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
I LIKE THAT--
LITTLE BIT.
LITTLE BIT OF OF SHALLOT...
SHALLOT.
JUST SALT AND WHITE PEPPER,
TINY LITTLE BIT OF WINE.
OH, JUST A BOTTLE.
CHICKEN STOCK
IN ON TOP OF THAT.
SOME OREGANO, SOME WHOLE THYME,
TINY LITTLE BIT OF BASIL,
CAYENNE PEPPER...
CAYENNE PEPPER.
CRUSHED RED.
SO WE'RE GONNA LET THIS
SIMMER DOWN A BIT, SON.
YEP, 20 MINUTES OR SO.
ADD THE ANDOUILLE IN
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
THERE WE HAVE IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
DUDE, YOU NEED A SHOVEL.
AND HOW ARE YOU
GONNA SERVE THIS?
THEY GO OVER DIRTY RICE.
MADE WITH CHICKEN LIVERS?
NO, DO IT WITH THE FRESH
ANDOUILLE BEFORE WE SMOKE IT.
GOTCHA. ADD A LITTLE
BONELESS CHICKEN THIGH.
AND THEN THE LADLE.
(whistles)
LITTLE BIT OF RED PEPPER.
LITTLE KISS OF SOME ONION.
MMM.
IT'S RICH, LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
TOUCH OF SMOKE.
ANYTHING THAT
THAT ANDOUILLE'S IN
IS ROCK STAR
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
MMM. THAT ROUX'S
REALLY NICE AND TIGHT...
MM-HMM.
REALLY CREAMY.
AND THEN YOU GOT THAT CHICKEN
ON TOP OF THAT DIRTY RICE. MMM.
EVERYBODY WORKS
HARMONIOUSLY TOGETHER.
THAT IS JUST EXCELLENT.
PUT THAT DOWN IN A HEARTBEAT.
CHICKEN AND SAUSAGE
éTOUFFéE.
IT'S DELICIOUS. THE SAUSAGE
IS AMAZING, THE CHICKEN.
EVERYTHING'S
ALWAYS WONDERFUL.
BISON CHILI.
THE MENU'S ALWAYS CHANGING.
AND IF YOU ASK MATTHEW
WHAT'S THE BEST PART
OF OWNING HIS OWN PLACE...
I GET TO CREATE STUFF
EVERY DAY, WHATEVER I WANT.
HE'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY ECLECTIC.
MINI PORK SHANK.
HE CAN DO ANYTHING.
FROM CUBAN TO CREOLE...
(Matthew) SHRIMP CREOLE.
TO BANANAS FOSTER FRENCH TOAST,
EVEN FROG LEGS.
FRIED TO PERFECTION,
GOLDEN GOODNESS.
FROG LEGS.
AND PEOPLE JUST REALLY
SEEM TO DIG 'EM.
OKAY, HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE BUTTERMILK.
YEAH, I'M GONNA SOAK THEM
IN BUTTERMILK OVERNIGHT.
AND THEN TAKE 'EM OUT,
POP 'EM IN THE DREDGE?
YEP.
A.P. FLOUR.
A.P.--ALL-PURPOSE.
PANKO BREADCRUMBS,
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
LITTLE SALT, KOSHER,
SOME WHITE PEPPER.
THAT'S IT.
INTO THE DREDGE.
FROG LEG TIME.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE WHOLE FARM
IN THERE, ARE WE?
WHY DON'T YOU GUYS
JUST HOP RIGHT IN THERE?
SKINNY CHICKEN. NOW WHAT ARE
WE GONNA SERVE THOSE WITH?
CHEDDAR AND JALAPEÑO
HUSH PUPPIES.
OH, OF COURSE,
THAT'S WHAT YOU SERVE WITH 'EM.
SELF-RISING CORNMEAL,
A.P. FLOUR AGAIN,
CANE SUGAR...
JALAPEÑOS.
DICED JALAPEÑOS,
A COUPLE OF EGGS.
GUY DOES IT LIKE ROCKY.
FINISH OFF
WITH SOME BUTTERMILK.
MIX THIS UP A LITTLE BIT
AND SEE WHERE IT IS.
WE WANT ENOUGH
TO HOLD IT TOGETHER,
BUT NOT TOO WET THAT IT'LL TURN
INTO A BLOB IN THE FRYER.
YEAH.
OKAY.
THIS CHEESE WILL REALLY
KIND OF HELP TIGHTEN IT
A LITTLE BIT, TOO.
THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
NOW THE HUSH PUPPIES
GO DOWN?
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK HOW SMALL THAT SCOOP IS.
S-M-ALL. SMALL.
WE READY?
YEAH.
(French accent) HELLO,
CRISPY FROGGY.
AND I THINK WE'RE GOOD
ON THE PUPPIES.
(normal voice) READY
FOR THIS?
PINOT GRIGIO AIOLI.
OKAY. FROG LEGS.
JUST HOP ON OVER
AND TRY THIS.
MMM. TASTES LIKE FROG.
(laughs)
IF YOU LIKE CHICKEN WINGS,
YOU'D LOVE THAT FROG LEG.
I LIKE THAT YOU DON'T PUT
TOO MUCH BATTER ON IT.
THE AIOLI GOES GREAT
WITH IT.
HERE'S THE CHEDDAR JALAPEÑO
HUSH PUPPY.
GET SOME NICE HEAT OUT OF
THE JALAPEÑO, LITTLE NUGGETS.
AND THEN WITH NICE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE.
NICE JOB. WAY TO GO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
FROG LEGS.
I LOVE 'EM,
THE CRUNCHINESS OF THE BATTER.
A REAL NICE BREADING,
THE FLAVOR COMES THROUGH.
(man) PASTRAMI.
HOMEMADE AND YUMMY.
YOU CAN TELL THAT
IT'S BEEN MADE WITH CARE.
THANK YOU.
BELLEVUE PRETTY HAPPY
TO HAVE YA?
EVERYBODY SEEMS
TO HAVE A GOOD TIME.
THANKS A BUNCH.
YOU TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF.
NICE TO MEET YA.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
NEXT STOP...
THIS IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL.
WE'RE HEADING TO CALIFORNIA...
PORK CHOP FOR YOU.
TO PUT THE FORK TO MORE PORK.
REALLY GOOD.
SO HERE I AM
AT ONE OF MY FAVORITE CITIES
IN THE ENTIRE COUNTRY,
LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA.
NOW I USED TO WORK
ABOUT A MILE THAT WAY
AT A PLACE CALLED
PARKERS' LIGHTHOUSE
IN SHORELINE VILLAGE,
AND I LIVED ABOUT TWO MILES
THAT WAY IN BELMONT SHORE.
MAN, SO MANY GREAT MEMORIES,
BUT I LOVE ROLLING BACK
INTO TOWN
AND CHECKING OUT
SOME OF MY FAVORITE JOINTS
KIND OF LIKE SCHOONER OR LATER
BUT ALSO SOME OF THE NEW PLACES
THAT HAVE OPENED UP
LIKE THIS PLACE, AT LAST CAFE.
TWO PORK CHOPS, MEDIUM.
THE FOOD IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
I HAVE A BRICK CHICKEN
FOR YOU.
BRICK CHICKEN, DELICIOUS.
THE MAC-N-CHEESE
IS READY.
OH, THE MACARONI AND CHEESE
IS EXCELLENT!
GOURMET COOKING--
THIS IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL.
FROM FORMER HIGH-END CHEF
JOHN McLAUGHLIN...
ALL RIGHT, IT LOOKS GOOD.
WHO DECIDED GREAT COOKING
SHOULDN'T COST A FORTUNE.
IS THIS LIKE A NONPROFIT?
FRENCH POT ROAST, $10.50.
BRICK CHICKEN--
HALF A CHICKEN--$9.50.
AND FOR $10.25...
STUFFED PORK CHOPS.
THIS IS BEYOND GOOD.
THIS IS REALLY AWESOME.
THE GRAVY IS AMAZING.
WE MAKE OUR GRAVY WITH
CHICKEN BONES, TOMATO.
CHICKEN BONES AND TOMATOES?
THAT'S IT.
WITHOUT ANY FUSS AND FEATHERS.
I JUST TAKE CHICKEN BONES,
PUT THEM IN THE OVEN,
ROAST THEM
TILL THEY'RE REALLY BROWN...
OKAY.
A HOUR AND A HALF,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
ALL BROWNED UP.
THEN TOMATO.
SHOOT IT BACK IN THE OVEN,
BROWN THAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
LIKE A BROWN GRAVY
MAD SCIENTIST.
WHEN THE TOMATOES COOK SOMEWHAT,
COLD WATER TO COVER.
POP IT BACK IN THERE.
SO IS IT READY TO STRAIN NOW?
YEAH.
OH, YOU GOT THIS?
YOU MIGHT WANT
TO HOLD IT, YEAH.
OH, NOW HOLD THIS.
WOW, THAT IS THE CRAZIEST STOCK
I'VE EVER SEEN.
NO HERBS, NO SWEETNESS.
THAT COMES LATER.
WELL, ACTUALLY WE DON'T PUT
TOO MUCH IN IT AFTER, EITHER.
(laughs)
WHAT I NORMALLY DO
IS I REFRIGERATE IT,
THEN SKIM THE GREASE
OFF OF IT.
ADD SOME RED WINE,
SALT AND PEPPER,
THICKEN IT WITH A SLURRY.
LITTLE CORNSTARCH.
JUST LET IT COME TO A BOIL
AND SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
WAY MORE FLAVOR
THAN I ANTICIPATED.
NOW WHAT?
WE SAUTé APPLES AND ONIONS FOR
THE STUFFING FOR THE PORK CHOP.
START OUT WITH A LITTLE BUTTER,
A LITTLE OIL, TOO.
BUTTER FOR FLAVOR,
OIL TO COOK.
ONIONS, APPLES.
GRANNY SMITH?
YEP.
NICE, FIRM TEXTURE.
SALT AND PEPPER.
AND THAT'S IT.
TAKE THAT AND MIX THAT
INTO THE BREAD
THAT WE'RE GONNA BE PUTTING FOR
THE STUFFING INTO THE CHOP.
YEP.
START WITH SOME DRY BREAD.
NOW THE SAUTéED APPLES
AND ONIONS THAT WE DID.
SOME CHOPPED PARSLEY.
CURLY, NOT ITALIAN.
MIXED DRIED HERBS,
DRIED CRANBERRIES.
SO CURRENTLY YOU'RE NOT
PUTTING ANY CURRANTS IN?
CURRENTLY NOT.
A LITTLE CINNAMON,
A LITTLE SALT.
BLACK PEPPER,
ONE EGG, VEGGIE STOCK.
JUST MIX IT UP JUST UNTIL
IT KIND OF COMES TOGETHER.
OKAY, THAT'S IT.
ALL RIGHT, GRAB THE CHOP.
WE'RE GONNA LIGHTLY MARINATE
THE CHOPS.
CHOPPED GARLIC, SOME HONEY,
BLACK PEPPER, A LITTLE SALT,
SOY SAUCE.
SOME OF MY
FAVORITE INGREDIENTS HERE.
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
A LITTLE CITRUS.
SOME OLIVE OIL.
DISSOLVE THE HONEY.
SO MARINADE'S MADE.
TELL ME ABOUT THE CHOPS.
THEY'RE ALREADY
LIGHTLY BRINED.
FROM YOUR BUTCHER?
YES.
OKAY, SO WE GO AHEAD,
SET 'EM UP.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING GLAZE.
HOW LONG WILL THESE MARINATE?
TWO OR THREE HOURS.
THEN WE'LL STUFF 'EM
TO ORDER.
YES.
I LIKE IT. OPEN WINE.
THIS ONE'S READY TO GO THEN.
YEAH.
LET'S COOK IT. DIG IT.
OLIVE OIL, JUST BROWN IT.
SALT AND PEPPER.
ONCE I THINK IT'S BROWN,
I FLIP IT
AND JUST GO AHEAD
AND THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
FINISH IT IN THE OVEN,
SEVEN, EIGHT MINUTES.
AND WHAT WILL THIS
BE SERVED WITH?
MASHED POTATOES,
FRESH VEGETABLES,
OUR BEAUTIFUL
HOMEMADE GRAVY.
THE MAGIC GRAVY.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. TELL YOU WHAT, JOHN BOY,
YOU KNOW HOW TO COOK.
THE CHOP IS SUPER TENDER.
THE STUFFING IS JUST--
THAT'S ALL THE RAVE--THE APPLES,
THE MARINADE ON THE OUTSIDE,
THE GARLIC AND THE SOY,
LITTLE CITRUS--YOU TIED IT
ALL TOGETHER, MAN.
THANK YOU.
WAY TO GO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NICE JOB. REALLY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
PORK CHOP FOR YOU.
I HAVE NEVER HAD A PORK CHOP
THAT WAS ANY MORE TENDER
AND JUICY AND MOIST.
THE GRAVY'S WONDERFUL, TOO.
I'LL BE MAKING THAT AT HOME.
I'D EAT THAT ON A SHOE. MMM.
WE SERVE IT ON EVERYTHING,
NO SHOES.
BUT HOW ABOUT MEAT LOAF...
MOIST, TENDER, VERY FLAVORFUL.
OR POT ROAST...
IT'S JUST MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH.
EVEN POLENTA WITH
FRESH PORTOBELLO MUSHROOMS.
ONE OF MY ALL-TIME
FAVORITE DISHES.
IT'S A BLACKBOARD SPECIAL,
BUT WE HAVE IT ALMOST EVERY DAY.
PORTOBELLO WITH POLENTA.
START WITH SOME WATER,
HALF-AND-HALF...
OKAY.
ABOUT A TABLESPOON OF SALT,
PEPPER.
BRING THAT TO A BOIL.
SLOWLY WHISK IN THE CORNMEAL.
LET THAT COOK
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
UNTIL WE'RE NICE
AND TIGHT.
YEAH. ADD SOME BUTTER.
GO AHEAD AND PUT SOME CHEESE.
A LITTLE PARM
STIRRED IN THERE.
THAT'S IT.
HALF A SHEET TRAY.
SPRINKLE A LITTLE
COLD WATER ON THERE,
IT WON'T STICK TO THE PAN.
OKAY.
POUR IT ON
AND SMOOTH IT OUT.
MMM. NICE AND CREAMY.
THAT'LL BE GREAT.
JUST LET IT COOL.
IT'S COOLED DOWN.
CUT 'EM IN SQUARES
AND LIFT IT OUT OF THERE...
YOU CAN DO IT.
YOU CAN DO IT. GOOD JOB, JOHN.
AND THEN TRIANGLES,
AND THEN I JUST BROWN 'EM
ON THE FLATTOP.
DIG IT.
LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
OKAY. WHAT DO WE DO
WITH THE MUSHROOMS?
SO WHAT WE DO
IS REMOVE THE STEM.
OKAY.
WITH A SPOON,
SCRAPE THE GILLS OFF.
WE'LL SLICE 'EM UP
PRETTY THIN.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND SAUTé THOSE--
A LITTLE OIL, BUTTER,
MUSHROOMS, LITTLE GARLIC,
SALT AND PEPPER,
AND SCOOT IT IN THE OVEN.
THESE ARE READY
TO TURN THERE, JOHNNY.
PRETTY NICE. OKAY.
OKAY, PORTOBELLO MUSHROOMS.
I'M GONNA HIT IT
WITH A SPLASH OF RED WINE,
DELICIOUS GRAVY.
INFAMOUS BROWN GRAVY.
A LITTLE BUTTER, CHOPPED
PARSLEY, SALT AND PEPPER.
JUST COOK IT UNTIL
IT COMES TOGETHER.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
POUR IT ON THE PLATE.
MMM.
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE PARMESAN
CHEESE AND THE POLENTA.
LOOK AT THAT.
BIG SELLER HERE?
BIG TIME, YEAH--6 BUCKS.
HMM. MM-HMM. THAT SAUCE
IS SO NICE AND RICH.
IT'S SUCH A SIMPLE DISH.
YOU DID IT SO NICE.
I'D EAT THIS ONE
ALL DAY LONG. MMM.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU.
PORTOBELLO WITH POLENTA.
IT TASTES PERFECT.
(man) THIS IS GREAT.
I LOVE THIS.
EVERYTHING YOU'VE HAD HERE
YOU'VE ENJOYED?
ALWAYS.
WHATEVER YOU EAT
IS GONNA TASTE REALLY GOOD.
IT'S GONNA BE FRESH.
YOU THINK?
I HAVE A LOT OF FRUIT TREES
IN MY BACKYARD.
AND HE'S PUTTING THEM
TO WORK...
LEMONS, LIMES...
ON THIS LOCAL FAVORITE.
YELLOWTAIL.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YOU CAN SURE CRANK OUT
SOME FLAVOR.
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS.
AT THE AT LAST CAFE
IN LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA...
POT ROAST FOR YOU.
OWNER JOHN McLAUGHLIN...
(John) ALL RIGHT.
IS DOING WHAT HE CALLS
GOURMET COMFORT FOOD.
A LOT OF INTERESTING FLAVORS,
DIFFERENT COMBINATIONS,
VEGETABLES.
EVEN FRUIT
FROM HIS OWN BACKYARD.
OH, SMELLS AWESOME.
SMELL THAT.
LEMONS, LIMES, FRESH YUZU,
I HAVE A YUZU TREE.
WOW, YOU HAVE A YUZU TREE.
JAPANESE CITRUS, REALLY STRONG,
GREAT TO COOK WITH.
VERY REFRESHING AND NOT
TOO SWEET OR OVERPOWERING.
ESPECIALLY ON
THIS LOCAL FAVORITE.
THE YELLOWTAIL'S GREAT.
OKAY, A LITTLE YELLOWTAIL.
YEAH, THE LOCAL FISH.
WELL, IT'S HALF
OF A LOCAL FISH.
HALF A LOCAL FISH.
GONNA GO AHEAD AND REMOVE
THE SKIN AND THE PIN BONES.
OKAY.
TRYING TO FIND THE BONES
WITH YOUR FINGER.
VERSUS YOUR TOE?
NOW I JUST GO AHEAD
AND CUT PORTIONS.
BIG PORTIONS THERE.
WE DON'T WANT ANYBODY
TO LEAVE HUNGRY.
NOW WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO WITH THIS?
THEY'RE PAN-SAUTéED,
AND WE MAKE A SAUCE
WITH THE LIME AND GINGER,
BUT IT'S LIKE A LOT OF OTHER
LITTLE CITRUSY THINGS IN THERE.
CITRUSY THINGS.
YEAH.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
YELLOWTAIL.
OKAY.
SALT AND PEPPER.
BROWN IT, THEN FLIP IT
AND THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
WAIT A SECOND.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT IT IN THE PAN,
BROWN IT ON BOTH SIDES,
PUT IT IN THE OVEN?
YEAH.
TAKE A LOOK, FOLKS.
NOW I'LL GO AHEAD
AND SHOOT IT IN THE OVEN.
THE NICE THING ABOUT
COOKING IT IN THE OVEN
IS IT'S A NICE,
ROUND, EVEN HEAT TO FINISH IT.
I DO MY PORK CHOPS
A LOT THAT WAY AND SO DO YOU.
JUST GONNA SET IT ASIDE
FOR LATER.
JUST START ADDING
THE OTHER INGREDIENTS.
GREEN ONIONS, DICED TOMATOES,
JULIENNE GINGER--
WHAT I DO IS I SOAK IT
IN RED WINE JUST TO PRESERVE IT.
ALL OUR VARIED CITRUS ZEST
AND LIME.
INTERESTING DISH.
YEAH. CITRUS SEGMENTS.
GO AHEAD AND GET THAT GOING.
NICE.
A BEAUTIFUL VINTAGE RED WINE,
CREAM, BUTTER,
SALT AND PEPPER.
LITTLE CHOPPED PARSLEY.
THAT'S IT.
SAUCE IS READY?
SAUCE IS READY.
FISH IS READY.
LIME AND GINGER SAUCE.
LOOK AT THAT.
(whistles)
BROTHER, I WANT
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING,
YOU GOT THE SMALLEST KITCHEN,
ONE OF THE SMALLEST
I'VE EVER SEEN,
BUT YOU CAN SURE CRANK OUT
SOME FLAVOR.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
IT'S SUPER FAST.
IT'S SUPER FRESH.
AND IT'S SUPER FLAVORFUL.
THE CITRUS
ISN'T OVERBEARING.
THE GINGER GIVES
A GREAT PERFUME.
CREAM IS GENTLE AND LIGHT.
THE YELLOWTAIL'S PERFECT FOR IT.
AND IT'S A MONSTER PORTION.
I WOULDN'T CHANGE
A THING ABOUT THIS.
NICE JOB. WAY TO HAMMER
THAT OUT, JOHN. MAN!
THANK YOU.
OKAY, SO WHO'S GOT
THE YELLOWTAIL?
PICK IT UP. IT'S READY.
THE SAUCE IS UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
(man) AT THE END OF THE DAY,
THAT'S WHY YOU COME BACK.
THE FOOD IS FABULOUS.
WE HAVE A MEAT LOAF
FOR YOU.
SO YOU'LL BE BACK?
OH, YEAH.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE EXPERIENCE
OF EATING THE FOOD.
IT'S THE EXPERIENCE
OF WHERE YOU ARE,
WHO YOU'RE WITH
AND WHAT YOU WALK AWAY FROM.
AND YOU SEEM LIKE YOU WALK AWAY
FROM A GREAT EXPERIENCE.
ABSOLUTELY.
THE PRICING
IS IMPORTANT...
YES, IT IS.
BUT EVEN IF IT WERE MORE--
OH, NO,
I WAS GONNA SAY...
EVEN IF WAS MORE EXPENSIVE?
DON'T WORRY.
I WON'T TELL HIM.
NO, I DID NOT SAY THAT.
I DID NOT SAY THAT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHO BROUGHT
RYDER'S CHAIR HERE?
WHAT IN THE WORLD?
(man) IT'S A NEW GAME.
(laughter)