HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVES-INS AND DIVES.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT'S GOOD.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
SEVEN SEAS SOUP.
GLOBE-TROTTIN'...
WE HAVE SOME
BASQUE-STYLE BEANS.
IN RENO.
HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S AN INSTITUTION.
IT'S A RENO STAPLE.
THE CORNER FAVORITE...
LAMB STEW, OXTAIL...
WHERE AUTHENTIC
BASQUE COOKING...
GOOD HEARTY PEASANT FOOD.
MEANS 42 YEARS OF COMFORT FOOD.
MMM.
HUMUNGOUS FLAVOR.
IN LOS ANGELES...
FISH IS READY.
THE SMALL CAFé...
MAGNIFICENT FOOD.
CRANKING OUT...
MMM.
BIG SALVADORAN FLAVOR.
OUTSTANDING.
AND IN JACKSONVILLE...
GARLIC MUSHROOMS.
THE PEASANT KITCHEN...
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
WHERE THE MENU...
(man) TASTE THE WORLD
WITHOUT FEELING LIKE
YOU'VE LEFT
YOUR LIVING ROOM.
NEEDS A MAP OF ITS OWN.
CHORIZO.
YOU HAVE SOME
ITALIAN INFLUENCE,
SOME INDIAN INFLUENCE,
SOME SPANISH INFLUENCE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM, RENO, NEVADA,
THE BIGGEST LITTLE CITY
IN THE WORLD,
KNOWN FOR SO MANY THINGS--
HOT AUGUST NIGHTS CAR SHOW,
THE RENO AIR RACES,
STREET VIBRATIONS,
THE MOTORCYCLE FESTIVAL--
I MEAN, YOU NAME IT,
THE LIST GOES ON AND ON.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS I DIG
IS THIS 42-YEAR-OLD
BASQUE RESTAURANT
THAT--GET THIS--
IT'S GOT A HOTEL ON TOP.
THIS IS LOUIS' BASQUE CORNER.
CHICKEN BASQUE.
ORDER OF OXTAILS
AND RABBIT.
I GOT SHRIMP WORKING.
IT'S AN INSTITUTION.
IT'S A RENO STAPLE.
IT'S HARD TO FIND
GOOD ORIGINAL BASQUE FOOD.
THIS IS AUTHENTIC.
SWEETBREAD COMING UP.
FROM LAMB STEW, OXTAIL...
THE RABBIT'S AWESOME.
GOOD HEARTY PEASANT FOOD.
THANKS TO LOUIS ERREGUIBLE...
HOW ARE YOU?
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT IN '67.
THIS PLACE WAS PACKED.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
THIS PLACE WAS PACKED?
THIS PLACE IS PACKED NOW.
LOUIS RAN THE KITCHEN HIMSELF
FOR ALMOST 30 YEARS...
HERE, READY.
UNTIL HE PASSED HIS RECIPES ON
TO LONG-TIME CHEF
FRANK VARGAS...
BEAUTIFUL.
LIKE THIS TOP SELLER...
ONE OXTAIL COMING UP.
ON THE MENU FROM THE BEGINNING.
IT'S GREAT. IT JUST KIND OF
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
SO, UH, WHAT ARE WE
GONNA COOK TODAY?
WE'RE GONNA
DO SOME OXTAILS.
GIVE IT TO ME.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR OXTAIL.
SO NO OIL, NO HERBS,
NO NOTHING...
NO.
IN THE PAN.
THEN WE THROW THESE
IN THE OVEN...
OKAY.
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND PULL THE BONES RIGHT OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL NICE AND BROWNED.
OKAY.
START OFF WITH SOME FLOUR.
OKAY, AND THEN
WE'LL MIX IT ALL UP.
THIS WILL FALL DOWN AND MAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF A ROUX?
CORRECT.
AND THEN WE'LL
ADD THE WINE,
AND THIS IS JUST
A RED TABLE WINE.
WE'LL ADD THE CARROTS
AND THE CELERY, ONION...
OKAY.
SO THERE'S OUR MIREPOIX.
CHOPPED GARLIC--
WE BUY IT WHOLE,
AND WE CHOP IT OURSELVES...
YOU CHOP IT YOURSELVES.
GOOD MAN.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
A LITTLE THYME,
A LITTLE PARSLEY
AND THREE BAY LEAVES.
THERE YOU GO.
AND TO THAT,
WE'LL PUT SOME BEEF BROTH.
ARE YOU MAKING THIS
YOURSELF?
OH, OF COURSE,
WE MAKE IT OURSELVES.
I GOT LOUIS ALL MAD AT ME
IN HERE.
ABSOLUTELY.
DON'T LET ME HEAR THAT.
SO WE'LL GET THIS ALL MIXED IN,
COVERED UP,
PUT IT IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT THREE OR FOUR HOURS.
AND WE'RE RUNNING THIS
AT 350?
YES.
WE'RE READY TO PULL 'EM OUT.
THERE WE GO.
OH, YOU STRAIN IT A LITTLE BIT
WHEN YOU SERVE IT UP.
YES, I DO.
THAT'S
A DINNER-SIZE PORTION?
THAT IS
A DINNER-SIZE PORTION.
THAT'S A LOT OF MEAT.
MMM.
ARE YOU KIDDIN' ME?
HUMUNGOUS FLAVOR.
THINK ABOUT A SUPER FLAVORFUL,
OVER-THE-TOP BEEF STEW--
MMM--
WITH A TON OF BEEF IN IT.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'LL GET.
SOAKING IT UP WITH THE BREAD
RIGHT THERE,
GETTING SOME OF THAT BROTH.
MMM.
PRETTY GANGSTER.
I'D COME BACK
AND HAVE THAT AGAIN, FOR SURE.
RIGHT ON.
OXTAIL HERE.
IT'S SUPER TENDER,
AND IT'S SUPER RICH.
AND IT JUST
TASTES EXCELLENT.
BASQUE BEANS.
IT'S TOTALLY FAMILY STYLE.
DO YOU GUYS WANT SOME?
YOU BET.
THEY JUST COME OUT
WITH BIG DISHES AND SERVE YOU.
ROAST LAMB HERE.
EVERYBODY SITS DOWN TOGETHER...
OH.
A LOT OF FOOD,
YOU ALL SHARE.
PORKCHOPS...
DID YOU GET OXTAIL?
AND BASQUE-STYLE BEANS.
I TRIED THE SWEETBREAD TODAY.
THAT WAS GOOD.
THE SWEETBREAD
IS THE THYMUS GLAND OF THE CALF.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, LOOK AT HIM.
HE'S NOT PICKING JUST ONE PIECE
LIKE SOME PEOPLE.
WELL, FANS OF TRIPLE "D,"
ONCE AGAIN,
I EMBARK ON A UNIQUE FOOD ITEM.
I'VE HAD LAMB'S TONGUE,
CAT FRIES,
LAMB FRIES, BEEF TONGUE,
TURTLE, PIG EAR, PIG TAIL,
AND NOW
WE ARE PREPARING OURSELVES
TO ENJOY THE THYMUS GLAND.
THIS IS FOR YOU.
♪♪
JUST KIDDING.
IT'S ABOUT AS TENDER AS ANYTHING
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
IF YOU'RE
GONNA TRY 'EM,
THIS IS THE WAY
TO GET AFTER 'EM.
WE SHOULD ALWAYS TRY SOMETHING
NEW AND DIFFERENT.
ORDER OF RABBIT.
IT'S JUST A GOOD EXPERIENCE.
I MEAN, I'M EATING RABBIT.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN, YOU DON'T GET
THAT IN EVERY RESTAURANT.
RABBIT STEW.
YES. WE NEED TO GET OUR PAN
NICE AND HOT.
THESE ARE THE KIND OF PANS
I LIKE--LITTLE BLACK IRON.
START OFF WITH ABOUT A CUP
OF OLIVE OIL.
AND WE'RE GONNA SEAR OUR RABBIT
RIGHT IN THAT OIL.
NOW THIS IS DOMESTIC
FARM-RAISED RABBIT.
CORRECT.
SO IT'S NOT QUITE AS GAMEY
AS WILD RABBIT.
CORRECT.
SO YOU PUT A LITTLE BROWN
ON THIS.
WE'RE GONNA
FLIP THESE AROUND.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE GARLIC SALT...
GARLIC SALT.
YES--AND A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPER.
BROWN IT
ON THIS SIDE,
DO TWO OR THREE BATCHES
OF THIS.
WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
IN THE SAME OIL,
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND BROWN SOME SHALLOTS.
'CAUSE THERE'S ALL THE FLAVOR
IN THE BOTTOM OF THAT PAN.
CORRECT.
GARLIC.
LITTLE BUTTON MUSHROOMS.
YES.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT ON THIS
AND JUST LET THESE MUSHROOMS
TAKE ON SOME OF THAT FLAVOR
OF THE ONIONS AND GARLIC?
CORRECT.
WE'LL THROW OUR RABBIT
INTO THE PAN.
I LIKE HOW HE SAYS
"OUR RABBIT."
THEN WE'LL THROW OUR MIXTURE
IN IT, TOO.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
WE START OFF
WITH OUR FLOUR.
AGAIN, THAT'LL HELP
BUILD THAT ROUX.
CORRECT.
AND THEN PARSLEY, THYME
AND JUST A COUPLE
OF BAY LEAVES.
OF COURSE.
THEN WE'LL ADD RED WINE,
BEEF BROTH
AND TOMATO SAUCE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA STIR THIS UP,
COVER IT UP WITH FOIL.
SEAL IT OFF NICE AND TIGHT,
IN THE OVEN, 350.
350 FOR ABOUT 3 HOURS
OR SO.
IS THE WABBIT WEADY?
IT'S READY.
WOW, DID YOU SEE THE ACTION
ON THAT CAMERA?
LET'S SEE THAT AGAIN.
IT'S LIKE THE, UH,
CAMERA IN HE NFL.
HE'S ON IT.
LOOK AT HOW DEEP AND RICH
AND BROWN THAT SAUCE IS.
IS THIS A NORMAL,
UH, NORMAL PORTION HERE?
SERVING, YES.
LOOK AT IT. IT JUST FALLS
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
I'VE BEEN WAITING TO DO THIS
ALL DAY.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
I WANT YOU TO THINK
OF TENDER, JUICY CHICKEN,
BUT WITH MORE RICHNESS
TO IT.
IT'S CREAMY.
THE GRAVY'S FANTASTIC.
I WOULD HAVE TO SAY,
THAT'S UP IN THE TOP FIVE
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
RIGHT ON.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT
GETTING THIS AS A CAREER.
(woman)
WHO'S DOING OUR RABBIT TODAY?
IT'S REALLY, REALLY TENDER,
FALLING OFF THE BONE
RIGHT THERE.
AND THE GRAVY ON TOP
JUST ADDS ICING ON THE CAKE.
WE HAVE SOME
BASQUE-STYLE BEANS.
YOU COME HERE ONCE,
AND YOU'RE HOOKED.
THIS IS MY SECOND TRIP
THIS WEEK,
AND I'LL BE BACK
SATURDAY NIGHT.
TWO STEAKS,
TWO ROAST LEG OF LAMB.
YOU COME IN AS STRANGERS,
YOU LEAVE AS FAMILY.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT THEY WANT TO DO.
THANKS, LOUIS.
I HAD A GREAT TIME, MAN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
BEEF TACOS READY.
WE'RE HEADING SOUTH TO L.A...
SEVEN SEAS SOUP.
TO HEAD SOUTH TO EL SALVADOR.
GOOD STUFF.
DUDE.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT'S GOOD.
SO HERE I AM ABOUT
A MILE AND A 1/2 EAST OF THE 405
ON VENICE BOULEVARD,
WHICH IS A MAJOR THOROUGHFARE
BETWEEN THE BEACHES
AND LOS ANGELES.
NOW ON THE RIGHT-HAND SIDE
IS A BUNCH OF MOVIE
AND TELEVISION STUDIOS
OVER THERE IN CULVER CITY,
AND ON THE LEFT-HAND SIDE,
WELL, YOU NAME IT,
THAT'S THE SUBURBS,
BUT IT'S HOME TO
A MEXICAN-SALVADORAN RESTAURANT
THAT'S BEEN OWNED AND OPERATED
BY THE SAME FAMILY
FOR 31 YEARS.
THIS IS GLORIA'S CAFE.
FISH IS READY.
IT'S JUST ABSOLUTELY
MAGNIFICENT FOOD.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC
AND AMAZING.
HOUSE SPECIAL--BURRITO...
THANKS TO OWNER
GLORIA FLORES...
OKAY.
WHO MOVED TO L.A.
FROM EL SALVADOR IN '67...
I HAD A DREAM
WHEN I CAME,
BUT I NEVER THOUGHT
IT WAS GONNA BE.
HOW DID YOU DO IT?
WELL, I WORKED REALLY HARD.
14 YEARS IN OTHER FOLKS'
RESTAURANTS...
HEY.
HOW'S EVERYTHING...
GLORIA SAVED ENOUGH
TO OPEN HER OWN...
FISH TACOS READY.
FIRST DOING MEXICAN FOOD...
BECAUSE PEOPLE DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT SALVADORAN FOOD?
EXACTLY.
AWESOME.
BACK IN 1995, I STARTED
SERVING SALVADORAN FOOD.
AND THAT TOOK OFF...
OKAY, SENORITA...
FROM TRADITIONAL PUPUSAS
MADE WITH MASA AND CHEESE
TO FRIED YUCCA AND PORK
TO THIS SALVADORAN CLASSIC...
(woman) CARNE ADOBADA--
PORK SIMMERED IN A TOMATOEY
AWESOME SPICY SAUCE.
IT'S JUST MADE TO PERFECTION.
OKAY, SO LET'S GET STARTED.
THAT'S A PIECE OF PORK.
I'M GONNA CUT IT.
YOU GOT A BONE
IN THIS ONE.
WE COOK IT
WITH THE BONE.
BECAUSE THERE'S FLAVOR
IN THAT.
YEAH.
SHE KNOWS EXACTLY
WHERE THAT BONE IS.
JUST CUTTING IT AROUND.
ALL THE PORK IN THERE.
PORK IN THERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MARINATE IT.
GREAT.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE...
TAPATíO...
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE...
GRANULATED GARLIC...
SOME BLACK PEPPER...
SALT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP.
ALL RIGHT.
PUT THE ONIONS
ON TOP.
SO WE PUT THE ONIONS
WE LET IT MARINATE FOR...
OVERNIGHT.
FOR 24 HOURS,
AND THEN WE POP IT IN THE OVEN,
350 FOR ABOUT 4 HOURS
TILL IT JUST PULLS APART.
YEAH.
LOOK AT
THE DEEP, RICH COLOR.
IS THAT YOUR WALLET
BACK THERE?
MMM.
WHAT?
OKAY, NOW YOU TAKE IT,
SHRED IT IN HERE.
SHRED IT IN THERE.
OKAY, NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
AND I MAKE ADOBADA SAUCE.
FIRST YOU PUT PEPPER AND ONIONS,
GARLIC, TOMATOES AND SALT.
OKAY.
WE LET IT COOK DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE THAT
MIXTURE AND PUT IT IN HERE.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME DE ARBOL CHILIES.
AND A LITTLE ANCHO,
ROASTED GUAJILLO.
IS THAT GOOD?
YEAH.
TOASTED SESAME SEEDS...
FRESH GARLIC...
MORE TOMATOES AND ONIONS...
TAPATíO...
ONE OF MY FAVORITE
HOT SAUCES.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
THERE WE GO.
SOME GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT
AND THEN SOME MEXICAN OREGANO.
READY?
THAT'S GOOD?
YES.
CAN I TRY IT?
OF COURSE.
THAT'S FINE,
I'LL TAKE--WHOA.
I'LL TAKE--OH, THAT'S GOOD.
I'LL TAKE IT LIKE THAT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS,
COOK IT.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL IT.
TO REDUCE IT?
YEAH.
AND THEN...
THE SECRET SAUCE
FOR THE ADOBADA.
ITALIAN DRESSING, FRESH GARLIC,
THIS IS VINEGAR...
APPLE CIDER,
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL.
I LOVE
YOUR MEASURING STYLE.
BLACK PEPPER, SALT...
OREGANO...
OREGANO.
THAT YOU'RE GONNA GRIND UP.
OH, YOU'RE JUST
GONNA HIT THE HAMMER.
SO NOW THIS IS GONNA GO
INTO THE ADOBADA SAUCE.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
FRY THE PORK.
COOK THE PORK
ONE MORE TIME.
PUT IT IN
THE ADOBADA SAUCE.
AND THEN GIVE IT A SQUIRT
OF THE SECRET SAUCE.
THAT'S WHAT'S GONNA PUT IT
OVER THE TOP. GOOD TO GO?
THIS IS A NORMAL PORTION.
OH, YEAH.
PUT YOUR ONIONS ON TOP.
AND THIS IS HOW WE DO IT,
HUH?
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. WOW. DELICIOUS.
YOU PICK IT UP
WITH YOUR TORTILLA, RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
YEAH, THAT WOULD BE A VERY
TRADITIONAL WAY TO EAT IT.
MY FAVORITE WAY TO EAT IT
WOULD BE LIKE THIS.
OUTSTANDING.
THE CHAMPION.
CARNE ADOBADA HERE.
(woman)
MELTS ALMOST IN YOUR MOUTH.
AND THE OUTSIDE
IS ALL NICE AND CRUNCHY.
THE TEXTURE OF THE PORK
CAN'T BE BEAT. I LOVE IT.
(man) AMAZING.
DID YOU JUST FLIP?
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
READY FOR TABLE TWO.
OH, THERE'S SO MUCH HERE
I CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT.
YOUR ENCHILADA PLATE, SIR.
I LOVE THE MEXICAN FOOD HERE.
IT'S AWESOME.
READY OVER HERE.
I USUALLY GO FOR
THE CARNE ASADA TACOS.
THE CHILE RELLENO,
IT'S LIKE THEY WENT TO A GARDEN
AND PICKED THE PEPPERS
THEMSELVES.
THE MEXICAN'S GREAT.
THAT SALVADORAN'S GREAT.
I GO FOR THE SALVADORAN, BECAUSE
IT'S REALLY SOMETHING SPECIAL.
LIKE THIS FAMILY RECIPE...
SEVEN SEAS SOUP.
THAT GLORIA HAS BEEN MAKING
SINCE SHE WAS 14.
IT'S MY FAVORITE DISH
ON THEIR MENU.
WELL, LET'S GO.
LET'S MAKE IT.
SO A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER.
ONIONS...
THERE WE GO.
BELL PEPPERS.
GREEN BELL PEPPER.
THESE TOMATOES
ARE ALREADY FRIED.
FRIED THE TOMATO.
CELERY, THEN THE CARROTS,
FRESH GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, CUMIN...
CUMINO...
BAY LEAVES,
OREGANO, SALT.
OKAY, NOW HOW LONG
ARE WE GONNA LET THAT COOK?
FOR 40 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE SHRIMP SHELLS.
HOLY MOLY.
SO THOSE
STEEP IN WATER.
UH-HUH.
SOME GARLIC...
SOME ONIONS...
OKAY,
AND A LITTLE SALT.
AND THOSE COOK
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
20 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE'LL STRAIN IT.
AND THEN WE'LL ADD IT
TO THE SOUP.
THAT'S THE BROTH.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
DO THE CRAB...
OKAY.
OCTOPUS, HALIBUT...
THE SCALLOPS...
AND THE SQUID...
CALAMARIS--AND THE SHRIMP GO
LAST, 'CAUSE THEY'LL OVERCOOK.
BECAUSE--YES.
OKAY.
NEXT WE ADD THE BROTH.
IS THIS FOR ONE PERSON
OR TWO PEOPLE?
FOR ONE PERSON.
(whistles)
SIMMERS
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
AND THEN THE SHRIMP...
AND THEN--TO BE SIMMERED
FOR ONE MINUTE.
OKAY, IS IT READY?
AND SERVE
IN ALL THIS SEAFOOD.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME CILANTRO.
THIS IS IT.
OH.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
DEEP, DEEP FLAVOR,
REALLY RICH.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU WILL GO NUTS,
I MEAN, LITERALLY, OUT OF
YOUR MIND COMING TO TRY THIS.
NICE BIG PIECE OF CRAB.
IT IS SO KILLER.
TAKE IT AWAY
FROM THERE?
I'M OUT.
(man) THE SEVEN SEAS SOUP--
GOOD STUFF.
DUDE.
(man) ONE OF MY FAVORITE PARTS
OF IT IS JUST THE BROTH.
IT'S JUST REALLY RICH.
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS.
GLORIA'S--IT'S THE WHOLE
PACKAGE. THE FOOD'S THE BEST.
CHEESE PUPUSAS ARE READY.
IF I WANT A HOME-COOKED MEAL
EL SALVADORAN-STYLE...
HERE WE ARE.
THIS IS THE PLACE
TO COME.
THANKS FOR INVITING ME.
I REALLY APPRECIATE THAT.
THANK YOU, GUY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU GOTTA COME MEET HER.
INCREDIBLE.
NEXT STOP...
EVERY SINGLE THING
IS MADE TO ORDER.
WE'RE HEADING JACKSONVILLE...
ROMAN GNOCCHI.
FOR HOMEMADE CHORIZO
DONE WITH DATES.
I REMEMBER EATING DATES
WHEN I WAS A KID.
SO HERE WE ARE IN THE RIVERSIDE
AREA OF JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA,
TO VISIT A JOINT WHERE THE CHEF
WAS BORN AND RAISED IN SPAIN.
NOW SINCE HE WAS ABOUT
16 YEARS OLD, HE'S BEEN COOKING
IN HIS FAMILY'S
SPANISH-STYLE RESTAURANTS
TILL HE FINALLY OPENED HIS OWN.
THIS IS 13 GYPSIES.
PORK KEBABS
AND PEASANT BREAD.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
GARLIC MUSHROOMS.
YOU CAN'T
TOP THE TAPAS.
THOSE TRADITIONAL SPANISH
SMALL DISHES...
THIS IS SO GOOD.
THEY MAKE UP
HALF THE MENU HERE...
SHRIMP IS ALMOST READY.
THE SHRIMP WAS DELICIOUS--
KIND OF SPICY.
ANGRY BULL.
BEST STEAK EVER.
OLD FAMILY FAVORITES
HOWARD KIRK GREW UP WITH
IN SPAIN...
PLATING THE PASTA.
FROM FAMILY RECIPES THAT WENT
WAY BEYOND HIS SPANISH ROOTS.
TASTE THE WORLD WITHOUT FEELING
LIKE YOU LEFT YOUR LIVING ROOM.
SO YOU HAVE
SOME ITALIAN INFLUENCE,
SOME INDIAN INFLUENCE,
SOME SPANISH INFLUENCE.
CHORIZO.
THE CHORIZO IS JUST
REALLY FRESH AND DELIGHTFUL.
AND WE'RE GONNA
SERVE THIS WITH...
SAUTéED PEARS
AND TUNISIAN-SPICED DATES.
OF COURSE.
I REMEMBER EATING DATES
WHEN I WAS A KID.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
GROUND PORK, 80-20, SEA SALT,
SPANISH PAPRIKA, CAYENNE,
BLACK PEPPER,
A LITTLE OREGANO...
SO SO FAR,
THE SEASONING TO MEAT RATIO
IS ABOUT 50-50.
YEAH--
MINCED GARLIC AND WHITE WINE--
MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
WE MAKE IT EVERY DAY.
SO IT DOESN'T TASTE BETTER
BY LETTING IT SET UP?
WE LET IT AGE
AT LEAST 24 HOURS.
AND THEN HOW
ARE WE GONNA COOK IT?
FORM IT INTO PATTIES.
SO THOSE
ARE READY TO GO?
YEP.
ONE OF THESE THINGS
IS NOT LIKE THE OTHER ONES.
ONE OF THESE KIDS
IS DOING THEIR OWN THING.
YEAH, NICE.
WE ALWAYS START WITH THE PEARS
FIRST. THEY TAKE LONGER TO COOK.
OKAY.
WHEN THEY'RE GETTING
A LITTLE COLOR TO THEM,
THEN WE WOULD
ADD OUR CHORIZO,
THEN THE TUNISIAN DATES,
SOME GROUND CLOVE, GINGER,
A LITTLE CINNAMON,
WHITE PEPPER, SUGAR...
CUMIN.
YEP.
OKAY.
AND, UH,
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
NOW YOU HAVE
THE CHORIZO GOING HERE.
IT SMELLS DYNAMITE.
SO DATES ARE DONE.
CHORIZO'S READY.
SAUTéED PEARS
ARE FINISHED OFF
WITH HONEY.
OUT OF A BEAR
OF ALL THINGS, TOO.
AND A QUASI-MELTED BEAR.
IT'S GOT
A GANGSTA LEAN.
HEY.
AND THEN EVERYBODY
COMES TOGETHER ON THE PLATE.
PARTY TIME.
NOW IS THIS A TRADITIONAL
TAPAS MENU ITEM?
THIS IS SOMETHING
YOU CAN DEFINITELY FIND
IN SOUTHERN SPAIN.
DUDE, THIS IS DIFFERENT.
SO LET'S LOOK AT THIS CHORIZO.
MMM.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
A LITTLE PORK
WITH A LOT OF FLAVOR.
NICE RECIPE.
THEN I WANT TO TRY THE PEAR.
THE SWEETNESS
OF THAT HONEY
AND THE FRUIT FLAVOR
OF THE PEAR--
AND HERE COMES THE FUNKY ONE,
THE DATE.
DARN, THOSE DATES
ARE DELICIOUS.
DID I JUST GIVE
A TRIPLE "D"?
BEING WARMED UP, HAVING A LITTLE
BIT OF A CRUNCHY EXTERIOR
AND HAVING SOME SPICE TO IT,
IT WORKS INCREDIBLY WELL.
THE HIGHLIGHT OF THE SHOW
DEFINITELY IS THAT CHORIZO.
ALL RIGHT,
FRESH CHORIZO AND PEARS.
OH.
HOW'S THE CHORIZO?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
WHAT I LIKE IS THE COMBINATION
OF THE SWEET AND THE SPICINESS.
ENJOY.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
I LOVE THE FOOD.
(man) THERE YOU GO.
IT'S GOT A UNIQUE
CULINARY POINT OF VIEW.
IT KIND OF FEELS LIKE
AN EXPLORATION.
IT GOES FROM COCONUT-MANGO
CURRIED CHICKEN...
SO GREAT.
TO HUMMUS WITH HONEY...
MMM.
TO THIS REALLY OLD,
OLD-WORLD FAVORITE...
THE ROMAN GNOCCHI.
NOT YOUR GRANDMA'S DUMPLING.
MMM.
THIS IS ACTUALLY THE FIRST
DOCUMENTED STYLE OF GNOCCHI.
LET'S GET IT GOING.
ALL RIGHT.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
WE SLICE OUR GARLIC FRESH.
EVERY TIME
YOU MAKE THIS DISH?
MM-HMM.
ADD YOUR MILK.
ACTUALLY YOUR MILK.
THE WHOLE MILK?
YEP.
IS THAT MY SALT
OR YOUR SALT?
THAT'S MY SALT.
SLOWLY STIR IN
THE SEMOLINA FLOUR.
AND THIS IS SO WE
DON'T GET "CLUMPAGE."
YEAH.
SO WHEN WE START
GETTING TOWARD THE END,
THEN WE JUST DUMP IT
ALL IN.
MY EFFORTS AT MAKING THIS
UN-LUMPO-LICIOUS,
AND HE JUST GOES AND JUST DUMPS
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
WE ADD
OUR MELTED BUTTER.
I LIKE HOW
IT JUST BECAME "OUR."
I'M DOING
ALL THE STIRRING.
I COULD'VE HAD YOU DO SOMETHING
THAT REQUIRED DE-BLINGING.
WE'RE GONNA ADD IN
OUR EGG YOLK...
NICE COLOR OUT OF THAT.
A WHOLE LOT
OF PARMESAN CHEESE.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S IT.
YOU TAKE IT.
YEP.
PUT IT ON THE TRAY,
FLATTEN IT OUT.
YEP.
OH, MY GOSH.
HE EATS IT
RIGHT OFF THE COOKIE SHEET.
MMM. GOSH.
SO WE'LL COOL IT DOWN.
YEP.
CUT SOME SQUARES OUT,
STACK IT THREE HIGH.
WE JUST CUT IT IN HALF
INTO OUR RECTANGLES,
SEPARATE 'EM AND WRAP 'EM IN
WAX PAPER AND THEN SARAN WRAP.
AND IN THE FRIDGE
AND HOLD IT
UNTIL IT GETS ORDERED.
THEN HOW WILL WE
HEAT IT UP?
WE HAVE PANS HERE.
AND YOU GET THREE
PER ORDER.
IT GETS COVERED
IN A MUSHROOM SAUCE,
A LITTLE SALT, LOTS OF
BLACK PEPPER, FRESH THYME.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR BEEF STOCK.
YOU MAKE IT YOURSELF?
WE DO. SAUCE IS REDUCING.
ADD BUTTER.
THE OTHER SIDE OF THIS
IS BROWNING.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
SO GNOCCHI'S DONE. WE GOTTA GET
'EM OFF HERE ONTO A PLATE.
AND THEN POUR THIS OVER THE TOP
OF THE ROMAN GNOCCHI.
FINISH IT OFF WITH A LITTLE
ASIAGO, PROVOLONE,
ROMANO AND PARMESAN.
THERE YOU GO.
(whistles)
MMM.
THIS IS MEGA FLAVOR.
SUPER CREAMY. MMM.
BUT BECAUSE OF THE WAY
YOU CRISP IT UP,
IT REMINDS ME OF POLENTA.
THE GRAVY
THAT GOES ALONG WITH IT
IS SIMPLE, YET, WOW,
THAT'S A LOT OF FLAVOR.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THIS. NICE JOB.
(woman) ROMAN GNOCCHI.
(woman) A DIFFERENT KIND
OF GNOCCHI
THAN I'VE EVER HAD BEFORE--
DELICIOUS.
(woman) IT'S DEFINITELY
A DIFFERENT TEXTURE,
AND IT JUST MELTED
IN YOUR MOUTH. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(man) THERE YOU GO.
IT'S REAL FOOD. EVERYTHING
IS HANDMADE, FROM SCRATCH.
RIGHT DOWN
TO ONE OF MY FAVORITES--
A SPICED HAM CALLED TASSO.
IT'S JUST...
WHEN WE COME BACK.
PORK-LICIOUSNESS.
THERE YOU GO.
GNOCCHI IS READY.
AT 13 GYPSIES
IN JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA...
I GOT IT.
CHEF AND OWNER HOWARD KIRK
IS TURNING OUT
SPANISH CLASSICS...
SHRIMP PIRI-PIRI.
DONE HIS WAY...
EVERY SINGLE THING
IS MADE TO ORDER. MMM.
AND TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH, LIKE
FRESH-BAKED PEASANT BREAD...
EVERY DAY,
SOMETIMES TWICE A DAY.
WITH ONE OF MY ALL-TIME
FAVORITES, HOME-CURED TASSO.
IT TASTES LIKE SPICED BACON.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OURS OUT OF,
IT LOOKS LIKE THE LOIN.
LOIN, YEAH.
WE USE THE FATTY SIDE.
TYPICALLY, IT WOULD BE
JUST CUT OFF AND CHUCKED.
JUST CUT IT A LITTLE BIT THICKER
INTO THE LOIN.
LEAVE SOME MEAT
CONNECTED TO THE FAT.
THAT'S GONNA BE MADE
INTO THE TASSO.
YEAH.
OKAY,
SO WHAT'S THE FIRST STEP?
TWO PARTS SALT,
ONE PART SUGAR.
OKAY. THIS IS JUST A FLAT-OUT
SUGAR-AND-SALT DRY CURE?
THAT'S IT.
PUT THIS OVER THE TOP.
MAT IT ON THERE.
NOW THIS IS GONNA
GO IN HERE,
AND HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS CURE?
TWO DAYS.
TWO DAYS
UNDER REFRIGERATION,
IT'S GONNA START TO PULL OUT
SOME OF THAT MOISTURE.
YOU HAVE TO BABYSIT IT
BOTH DAYS.
YOU HAVE TO DRAIN ALL THE FLUIDS
OUT OF IT.
AFTER DRAINING IT, YOU WOULD
RE-MASSAGE THE SUGAR AND SALT.
THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
RINSE IT
UNDER COLD WATER.
PAT IT SO THAT
IT'S REALLY, REALLY DRY.
YOU CAN SEE HOW
IT BECOMES A LOT MORE DENSE.
IT ALMOST BECOMES
A LITTLE BIT DRIED OUT.
AND NOW IS GONNA COME
THE SPICE MIXTURE.
SO WE START WITH SUGAR...
WOW.
THIS REALLY DRAWS OUT
THE BALANCE
BETWEEN SUGAR AND SALT--
PAPRIKA, CAYENNE...
A LITTLE
GRANULATED GARLIC...
ONION POWDER...
ALLSPICE...
AND ALLSPICE.
YEAH.
CRAZY COMBINATION.
GET IT ALL
MIXED UP TOGETHER.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA STAY ON THE PORK?
THREE DAYS.
SO THAT GOES BACK
INTO A PLASTIC BAG.
IT HANGS OUT
FOR ANOTHER THREE DAYS.
NOW WE TAKE IT OUT.
AT THIS POINT,
YOU JUST WIPE IT.
JUST BRUSH IT OFF
A LITTLE BIT
SO IT'S NOT CAKEY
AND FALLING OFF.
EXACTLY.
AND WE'RE GONNA FINALLY
COOK THIS THING...
YEP.
FIVE DAYS LATER?
FIVE DAYS LATER.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
SO NOW WE JUST TAKE
SOME THIN SLICES OF IT.
MMM.
YOU'RE A GOOD SLICER.
BUT YOU CAN'T SLICE
THAT WHOLE THING.
A QUICK SAUTé.
GOTTA HEAR THE SIZZLE.
OKAY, SO THIS IS JUST
A LITTLE CRISP ON BOTH SIDES?
YEP.
SO ALMOST TREATING THIS
A LITTLE BIT LIKE BACON.
YEP.
THIS IS A TYPICAL SERVING?
YEAH.
IT'S JUST...
LIKE NIAGARA MOUTH
RIGHT NOW.
(Howard) WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON SOME PEASANT BREAD.
PUT IT IN A PANINI PRESS.
SO GIVE IT A LITTLE CRUST
ON BOTH SIDES.
YEAH, MAKE IT NICE AND WARM.
ADD OUR TASSO.
AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT, MAN.
MMM.
IT'S PORK MEETS JERKY
MEETS SALAMI
MEETS SMOKED SALMON.
THERE'S ENOUGH FAT THAT IT
DOESN'T DRY OUT IN YOUR MOUTH
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT,
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH ON IT,
NOT OVERLY SALTY.
AND DO YOU KNOW WHY THE BREAD
GOES SO GREAT WITH THIS?
NICE CRUST, REAL NICE
FRESH FLAVOR TO IT.
THIS RIGHT HERE
IS SIMPLE, BASIC...
PORK-LICIOUSNESS.
EXCELLENT JOB, MAN.
WAY TO KNOCK IT OUT.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
TASSO.
CRISPY ON THE EDGES--
I ENJOYED IT.
THE WAY THEY COOK THEIR MEAT
DOWN, IT'S JUST PERFECT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S MY FAVORITE RESTAURANT
IN JACKSONVILLE.
GNOCCHI'S READY TO FLIP.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK,
BUT AS SOON AS SOMEONE SAYS,
"MAN, THAT WAS DELICIOUS,"
IT'S ALL WORTH IT.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE IN THIS FOR.
THAT'S WHAT I'M IN HERE FOR,
YEAH.
I DIG IT. I DIG IT.
WOW, WAS THAT A ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT? BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THAT'S A VERY GOOD FLAVOR,
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU MIX IT
WITH THE...
THAT WASN'T NICE.