HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
HEY!
HOMEGROWN AND HOMEMADE...
GOT OUR SHRIMP
AND GRITS.
IN LACKAWANNA, NEW YORK...
AWESOME FOOD.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT...
BEYOND BELIEF,
JUST WONDERFUL.
WHERE HOMEMADE ITALIAN...
SHREDDED MOZZ,
OVER HERE!
MEANS MAJOR LEAGUE
MEATBALLS...
THE MEATBALL IS HUGE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND MONSTER LASAGNA.
I DON'T KNOW IF I WANT
TO EAT IT OR CLIMB IT.
IN HAWAII...
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE LOCAL STOP...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
FOR A LOCAL FAVORITE.
IT'S BASICALLY RAW FISH.
AND THEY'RE DOING IT
25 DIFFERENT WAYS.
MMM.
MEGA GANGSTER FRESH.
ALL THE FLAVOR PACKED INTO THAT.
AND IN
LEXINGTON, SOUTH CAROLINA...
IT'S TYPICAL SOUTHERN FOOD.
THE ROADSIDE SHED
WHERE THEY'RE GROWING IT...
YOU GROW THESE
HERE ON YOUR FARM?
YES, YES.
AND COOKIN' IT,
SOUTHERN STYLE.
MMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF
THE HOT PEPPER VINEGAR.
I COULD CHUG THAT.
MMM.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO LET ME THROW
SOME NUMBERS AT YOU--
HOW ABOUT 7, 11 AND 200?
SEE, I'M IN
LACKAWANNA, NEW YORK,
RIGHT BY BUFFALO,
WHERE THIS GUY GREW UP AND LIVED
IN SEVEN DIFFERENT HOUSES
IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
NOW OVER THE COURSE
OF 11 YEARS,
HE MADE OVER 200 TRIPS
TO NEW YORK CITY
TO SAMPLE, TASTE AND RESEARCH
THE FINEST ITALIAN RESTAURANTS.
NOW YOU ADD UP THOSE NUMBERS,
WHAT DO YOU GET?
218, RIGHT? NO, THAT'S NOT
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
WHAT YOU GET
IS A NEIGHBORHOOD GUY
THAT COMES BACK
TO HIS HOME TURF,
AND IS SERVING UP
HANDMADE ITALIAN FOOD.
WELCOME TO
MULBERRY ITALIAN RISTORANTE.
LASAGNA FOR TABLE SEVEN.
THIS PLACE IS AWESOME.
I LOVE IT.
ORDER UP!
LOT OF ITALIAN FOOD IN BUFFALO.
HOW DOES THIS RATE?
I THINK IT'S THE BEST.
GNOCCHI MULBERRY!
THE FOOD--BEYOND BELIEF.
IT'S JUST WONDERFUL.
LIKE EATING AT HOME--
ITALIAN HOME.
NO SURPRISE THERE.
I GREW UP ITALIAN.
YOU LEARNED TO COOK
WITH YOUR MOM AND YOUR GRANDMA.
RIGHT DOWN THE STREET.
BUT OWNER JOE JERGE...
TABLE FOUR!
FIGURED OUT HIS FAVORITES
IN NEW YORK CITY.
AND EVERY TIME YOU GO DOWN,
YOU DO WHAT?
EAT. EAT LIKE CRAZY.
SO WHEN HE OPENED
THIS PLACE...
SHREDDED MOZZ,
OVER HERE!
HE BROUGHT HIS TWO WORLDS
TOGETHER.
ALL THE DIFFERENT THINGS
THAT I'VE TASTED AND TRIED
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF GRANDMA'S
TOUCH AND MOM'S TOUCH.
HOW LONG ON THAT
LASAGNA, BEN?
CHICKEN PARMESAN--
DELICIOUS.
HOMEMADE LOBSTER
RAVIOLI.
THERE'S MORE
LOBSTER IN THIS
THAN AT THE LAST
LOBSTER DINNER THAT I HAD.
TAKE A MEATBALL,
PLEASE?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE DOES
WITH HIS MEATBALLS,
BUT IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT SIZE
IS YOUR MEATBALL?
A LITTLE BIT BIGGER
THAN THAT.
ALL RIGHT, FRESH GROUND
BREADCRUMBS.
NOW IS THIS LEFTOVER BREAD THAT
YOU HAVE HERE IN THE RESTAURANT?
YOU GOT IT.
PARMESAN CHEESE, FRESH BASIL...
OKAY.
FRESH PARSLEY--
ITALIAN?
NO, THAT'S CURLY.
THAT'S CURLY.
WHY CURLY?
I LIKE THE TEXTURE
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
GARLIC.
DRY OREGANO, KOSHER SALT,
COURSE BLACK PEPPER.
MIX THAT ALL UP.
I LIKE THE FRESH
BREADCRUMBS.
80-20 GROUND BEEF.
AND HOW MANY MEATBALLS
DOES THIS MAKE US?
APPROXIMATELY 45.
FRESH GROUND PORK.
AND YOU'RE USING JUST
A REGULAR BURGER GRIND,
SO THIS IS GONNA BE A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF A DELICATE MEATBALL...
RIGHT.
A LITTLE FINER GRIND
ON EVERYTHING.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
I DIG IT.
SOME EGGS FOR BINDER.
EGGS.
THERE'S THE LIQUIDS
I'M LOOKING FOR.
MILK AND SOME
WARM WATER.
WHY WARM WATER?
UH, TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I DON'T KNOW.
REALLY?
YEAH, ALWAYS USED
WARM WATER, NEVER ASKED.
DON'T OVER MIX.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
WANT TO FEEL THAT?
WHOA!
THAT WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SALAD
AND A PIECE OF BREAD
WILL SET YOU RIGHT
FOR THE WHOLE DAY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYIN'.
YOU BAKIN' THESE,
FRYING THESE?
WE BAKE 'EM.
3/4 OF THE WAY?
UH, WE BAKE 'EM ALL THE WAY,
ABOUT AN HOUR AND 10 MINUTES.
LET'S SEE 'EM.
ALL RIGHT, I GET TO PICK?
SURE.
I PICK THAT ONE.
LOOK AT ALL THAT JUICE.
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD
MEATBALL.
ALL RIGHT...
JUST--I KNEW HE WAS
GONNA DO THAT TO ME.
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD
MEATBALL, MAN.
REALLY NICE AND TENDER,
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH,
BIG FLAVOR,
CUT IT WITH A FORK.
IT STAYS TOGETHER, YET,
WHEN YOU PUT IT IN YOUR MOUTH,
IT DISSOLVES.
DELICIOUS.
GOOD.
THE MEATBALLS--
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
THE MEATBALL IS HUGE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
WHATEVER YOU ORDER--
THE BEST IT CAN BE.
CAPRESE SALAD, PLEASE.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
HE'S MAKING THE MOZZARELLA
HIMSELF.
HE MAKES HIS OWN
MOZZARELLA?
YEAH, HE MAKES--SEE?
I NEVER HEARD OF THAT!
HE'S STRETCHING IT OUT,
ROLLING IT INTO ITSELF.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL. MMM.
IT'S FRESH. IT'S LIGHT.
IT'S FLAVORFUL.
IT JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
AND HOMEMADE, LIKE THE GNOCCHI--
BEAUTIFUL. THE SAUCES,
THE RAVIOLI.
AND THE ITALIAN SAUSAGE
IN THEIR HAND-STUFFED PEPPERS.
MMM, FEEL LIKE THIS IS
MY BUCKET OF POPCORN. OOH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE DOES
BACK THERE,
BUT I'LL LEAVE IT AT--
THE MAGIC'S IN THE KITCHEN.
AND FOR HIS NEXT TRICK,
JOE'S DOING 45 POUNDS
OF HANDMADE LASAGNA.
HANDMADE PASTA,
HANDMADE SAUCE. LET'S DO THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE'VE GOT
THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
DOUBLE ZERO.
DOUBLE--OH, THIS IS
DOUBLE ZERO?
DOUBLE ZERO, YES, SIR.
DOUBLE ZERO FLOUR
IS THE OPTIMUM,
REALLY HIGH GLUTEN.
SO WE'RE GONNA CREATE A WELL,
GET THE EGGS IN.
A LITTLE SALT.
NOW ARE YOU DOING
FOOD PROCESSOR,
OR THIS IS ALWAYS
HOW YOU'RE DOING IT?
ALWAYS BY HAND, 'CAUSE
IT'S THE RIGHT WAY TO DO IT.
A LITTLE OIL. THAT'S ABOUT
AS OLD SCHOOL AS IT GETS,
RIGHT HERE. HOW MUCH
WILL THIS MAKE US?
TWO LAYERS
OF LASAGNA.
OKAY, HOW MANY LAYERS
YOU GOT?
FOUR.
YOU'RE GONNA DOUBLE
THAT UP?
RIGHT.
(whistles)
NOW YOU'LL LET THIS REST,
WHAT, A HALF-HOUR?
WET TOWEL OVER IT.
OKAY, SO WE GOT OUR DOUGH
RESTED. WORK YOUR MAGIC.
A LITTLE SEMOLINA FLOUR,
AND CUT A LITTLE BIT OFF.
SO YOU'VE GOT SOMEBODY BACK HERE
FULL-TIME ALMOST DOING THIS?
WE DO IT BY COMMITTEE.
JUST MAKING IT
TO A WORKABLE SIZE,
SO YOU CAN GET IT
INTO THE MACHINE.
(squeaking)
I THINK IT COULD USE
A LITTLE OIL.
YEAH, NO QUESTION.
NICE AND THIN.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
GREAT.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN,
BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA
BUTTER THIS PAN,
AND I'M GONNA THROW
SOME PANKO IN THERE.
JUST GET THESE FRESH SHEETS
AND BUILD A WALL FIRST.
I FEEL LIKE I'M AT SOME
CAKE DECORATING COMPETITION,
AND YOU'RE MAKING
THE LASAGNA CAKE.
HOW MANY OF THESE
DO YOU MAKE A DAY?
TWO OF 'EM EVERY DAY,
THREE ON SATURDAYS.
A LITTLE SAUCE.
YOU MAKE
THE TOMATO SAUCE, TOO?
ABSOLUTELY.
MEATBALLS, PLEASE.
ALL THAT TIME AND ATTENTION
YOU DID TO THOSE MEATBALLS,
YOU'RE JUST GONNA GO
AND SLICE 'EM RIGHT UP,
THROW 'EM RIGHT
ON THE BOTTOM OF THIS THING.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WOW. A LITTLE MOZZ
AND PARM COMBO.
ANOTHER SHEET
OF PASTA.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
SAUCE ON THERE.
NOW CHICKEN--WE'RE GONNA
GET THE WHOLE COOP IN THERE.
MORE MOZZ AND PARM.
RIGHT.
ANOTHER SHEET OF PASTA,
AND THEN WHAT?
THE STUFFED HOT PEPPER
MIXTURE.
JUST NEEDS A LITTLE
BIT OF SAUCE FIRST.
NOW SAUSAGE
AND PEPPERS.
I FEEL LIKE I'M
IN LASAGNA SURGERY HERE
AT FLAVOR TOWN MEMORIAL.
DR. JOE HAS BEEN
WORKING FEVERISHLY.
THEN ANOTHER LAYER
OF THE PASTA,
AND THEN THE RICOTTA
ON TOP...
YES, SIR.
WHICH IS TOSSED
WITH A LITTLE...
FRESH PARSLEY
AND A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
I THINK OUR PATIENT
IS PROGRESSING NICELY.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
MORE SAUCE ON THERE,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA FOLD THIS OVER.
BAKE IT UP,
NICE, NICE.
THINK WE'LL COVER THE PATIENT.
I EXPECT A FULL RECOVERY,
PROBABLY WITHIN
THE NEXT HOUR OR SO.
AT WHAT TEMPERATURE?
375.
LIKE IT. LOOK AT THAT.
OVER THE TOP
WITH THE MARINARA?
RIGHT.
SOMEONE GET IN HERE
AND SPOT ME.
THAT'S SERIOUSLY
THE PORTION.
GARNISH WITH SOME
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO?
AND SOME FRESH BASIL.
MR. BUNYAN, I DON'T KNOW IF
I WANT TO EAT IT OR CLIMB IT.
THAT'S THE WAY WE DO IT.
LOOK AT THIS RIGHT HERE.
STICKS TOGETHER. MMM.
WOW, MAN.
GOOD?
THAT'S NOT GOOD, THAT'S GREAT.
IT'S RICH, IT'S FLAVORFUL,
EVERYTHING YOU WANT
A LASAGNA TO BE.
AND QUALITY. MMM.
MY MAN.
NICE JOB, JOE. GONNA HAVE
TO GET YOU YOUR TATTOO.
THAT'S SOME GANGSTER
LASAGNA RIGHT THERE.
I DON'T WHIP THAT OUT
ALL THE TIME.
THAT LASAGNA--
THAT DESERVES IT.
JUST A LOT OF MEAT.
IT'S NICE AND SPICY. IT'S GOT
THE HOT PEPPERS IN THERE.
DID YOU REALLY EAT
THAT WHOLE MOUNTAIN?
I'M TRYING
TO FINISH THE REST.
I'M WAVING THE FLAG, MAN.
I'M DONE.
(girl) AWESOME FOOD.
I WOULD COME HERE AND MUNCH
EVERY SINGLE DAY THAT I COULD.
ORDERING A SUMMER CAPRESE,
PLEASE!
SO YOU GUYS
WILL BE BACK?
OH, YEAH, WITHIN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS.
THIS WAS A KICK.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S SOME MONSTER LASAGNA,
DUDE--MONSTER.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
CHEERS.
GOOD DUDE.
UP NEXT...
HOW CAN I HELP
YOU, SIR?
WE'RE HEADING TO HAWAII...
ANYTHING ELSE?
FOR AN ISLAND FAN FAVORITE.
POKE IS AN OLD
HAWAIIAN TRADITION.
NOW HOW MANY DIFFERENT TYPES
OF POKE WILL YOU HAVE AT A TIME?
WE SHOULD HAVE AT LEAST
25-PLUS.
SO NEW YORK CITY'S GOT
ITS CLASSIC PIZZA JOINTS,
AND CHICAGO, WELL,
THEY GOT THE HOT DOG STANDS.
CALI--GOT THE TAQUERIAS,
SO IT'S ONLY FITTING THAT HAWAII
WOULD HAVE POKE PLACES.
YOU KNOW, KIND OF LIKE
THE HAWAIIAN SOUL FOOD,
THE FRESH CUBED FISH
MIXED WITH THE HAWAIIAN SALT
AND THE SEAWEED,
SO HERE WE ARE AT A JOINT
WHERE A YOUNG LOCAL CHEF
HAS TAKEN HIS CULINARY
EDUCATION AND EXPERIENCE
AND PUT HIS OWN SPIN ON
A TRADITIONAL HAWAIIAN FAVORITE.
WELCOME TO POKE STOP.
WHAT YOU WANT?
KAPAKAHI.
POKE IS AN OLD
HAWAIIAN TRADITION.
HERE YOU GO.
IT'S BASICALLY RAW FISH,
CHOPPED UP.
IT'S KIND OF BEEN MARINATED.
IS ANY OF THE POKE
EVERY HOKEY?
SWEET ONION AHI.
IT'S VERY HAWAIIAN.
JUST WHAT HAWAIIAN-BORN CHEF
ELMER GUZMAN GREW UP LOVING.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NOW HE'S DECIDED TO TAKE
HIS CHILDHOOD FAVORITE...
ALL RIGHTY.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL
AT HIS JOINT NEAR HONOLULU.
HERE YOU GO.
SO YOU'RE TAKING
A TRADITIONAL HAWAIIAN DISH,
AND THROWING A LITTLE
ASIAN SPIN TO IT.
YES.
LIKE AHI TUNA WITH GARLIC
AND JAPANESE STYLE SOYBEANS,
AND THIS ONE--
SPICY KOREAN OCTOPUS.
ALL RIGHTY!
HEY!
HE'S EVEN USING A FISH
THEY DON'T SEE MUCH
IN THIS PART
OF THE PACIFIC.
SALMON POKE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HEY, LET'S GET
THE POKE ON.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE GOT HERE
A SIDE OF SALMON.
ALL WE'RE GONNA DO
IS CUT THE BELLY OUT.
WE'RE GONNA FILET
THIS BAD BOY. BAM.
BAM? HE'S THROWING AROUND
THE "BAM."
CUBE IT, ALL RIGHT,
PUT IT IN A BOWL.
SWEET ONIONS HERE.
OH, BY THE WAY,
I'M THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
THERE'S NO BIGGER ARMBAND
THAN MINE.
USING EMERIL'S LINE
AND WEARING MY WRISTBAND.
OKAY.
GREEN ONIONS,
HAWAIIAN SALT.
EVEN THOSE BIG PIECES
OF SALT LIKE THAT--
THAT'S GONNA BREAK DOWN
FAST ENOUGH?
IT'S GONNA BREAK DOWN.
WHEN YOU TAKE A BITE AND YOU
HAVE SOME CRUNCH IN THERE,
UNBELIEVABLE. SOME CHILI FLAKES
GIVES IT SOME HEAT.
UM--
SOME SEAWEED
AND TOASTED SESAME SEEDS
AND A LITTLE DRIED BONITO FLAKE.
A PINCH OF SUGAR,
SOY SYRUP
REDUCED DOWN.
DO YOU MAKE THIS?
YES, WE DO.
IT'S A SWEET SOY,
WE CALL IT, WHEN YOU BUY IT.
SWEET SOY--YEAH. ONCE WE
SEASON IT, IT'S READY TO GO.
COUPLE STIRS,
WE'RE SNACKING.
MY MOUTH'S STARTING TO--
MMM.
THERE WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S ALL THE FLAVOR,
PACKED INTO THAT.
MMM, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT'S GREAT.
MEGA GANGSTER FRESH.
THANK YOU.
SWEET TO SALT
TO A LITTLE SOUR,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE--NOTHING
IS OVERPOWERING ANYTHING ELSE.
DUDE, YOU KNOW
WHAT THE KICKER IS?
MMM, THAT LITTLE CRUNCH
OF THE SEA SALT.
ONE OF THE BEST WAYS I'VE HAD
SALMON. YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
VERY TENDER, VERY MOIST,
BURSTING WITH FLAVOR.
THIS IS VERY,
VERY GOOD POKE.
THIS IS KAPAKAHI.
NOW HOW MANY DIFFERENT TYPES
OF POKE WILL YOU HAVE AT A TIME?
WE SHOULD HAVE AT LEAST
25-PLUS.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA
EAT SOME THINGS
THAT WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THEY CAME FROM.
LIKE LIMPETS, A SHELLFISH
THE LOCALS CALL OPIHI.
OPIHI WITH THE AHI.
SCARF DOWN
ONE OF THOSE LIMPETS.
THAT'S SUCH A BIG,
RICH FLAVOR.
THAT IS LIKE THE PREMIUM
OF ALL HAWAIIAN SALADS.
YES.
AND THIS IS THE ROYALTY
OF HAWAIIAN FISH.
ORDERING TWO MOIS!
A.K.A., THE KING'S FISH,
SEASONED AND DEEP FRIED.
OKAY, MOI--
GIVE IT A LITTLE SCORE.
WHOA, YOU REALLY
GIVE IT A SCORE.
YEAH.
YOU GIVE IT
A CHECKERBOARD.
I'M GONNA PUT
SOME SPICE IN HERE--
KOSHER SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC...
ONION POWDER,
GROUND PEPPER.
GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
PAPRIKA, ALL RIGHT...
A LITTLE CAYENNE,
A LITTLE OREGANO
AND A LITTLE THYME.
AND THYME. SO ONCE
I MIX IT IN--
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME SPICE
IN HERE, IN THE CORNSTARCH,
AND JUST THE MOI--
SO YOU OPEN IT UP,
MAKE SURE THAT YOU GET
THE CORNSTARCH DOWN
IN THE CREVICES, OKAY.
YEP, AND WE SHAKE OFF
THE EXCESS,
AND DEEP FRY IT.
350 DEGREES.
FOR ABOUT FOUR
TO FIVE MINUTES.
FOUR TO FIVE MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT UP.
I LIKE THE SIZE BOX
HE PUTS IT IN.
JUST A SQUEEZE OF LEMON.
MMM.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
THIS ISN'T SUPER FISHY FISH.
NO.
THE SPICE DOESN'T TAKE AWAY
FROM THE FLAVOR OF THE FISH.
THE SKIN HAS ITS OWN PROPERTIES
OF BEING CRUNCHY...
YEP.
AND A LITTLE BIT SALTY.
KILLER FRIED FISH.
THE MOI--IT'S LIKE
REALLY TASTY.
YOU CAN'T GET FOOD LIKE THIS
ON THE MAINLAND.
WHO MAKES UP
ALL THE RECIPES?
I DO, AND I JUST
PLAY AROUND WITH IT,
KEEP ON BUILDING
A LIBRARY...
AND ON THE SHELF UNDER "O"--
O'IO.
OOH, OH-E-OH!
IT'S A RAW FISH THAT'S POUNDED
INTO A PASTE.
BONEFISH.
BOY, I HOPE IT TASTES
A LOT BETTER THAN IT SOUNDS.
WE'RE JUST GONNA SCALE
THE DORSAL PART.
THAT'S WHERE THOSE
FAKE NAILS COME FROM!
YOU'RE GONNA
GIVE HIM A BATH?
GONNA GET A BATH.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
BUTTERFLY IT.
GOT "NIP TUCK" RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA SPOON
EVERYTHING FROM TAIL TO HEAD.
ALL GOOD STUFF IN IT.
WHAT WE'LL DO IS PRESS
EVERYTHING THROUGH.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF BONES
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SCALES,
AND A PINKY RING. LOOK AT THAT!
NONE OF IT MADE IT THROUGH.
SO WE'RE MAKING FISH SPAETZLE?
THAT'S COOL.
SOME HAWAIIAN SALT.
GREEN ONIONS.
I LIKE THE COLOR.
SWEET ONION.
AND CHILI FLAKES.
KUKUI NUT, ROASTED AND GROUND.
WHAT'S A KUKUI NUT
LOOK LIKE?
CANDLENUT.
WHAT'S A CANDLENUT LOOK LIKE?
DON'T SAY KUKUI NUT!
UH, LIKE A MACADAMIA NUT.
OKAY, RIGHT DOWN
TO THE GENERIC TERM
RIGHT OFF THE BAT
FOR ME.
OGO--SEAWEED.
AND HERE'S THE KICKER--
ICE WATER.
"HERE'S THE KICKER"?
YEAH.
WHAT ARE YOU,
USING MORE OF THE LINGO?
ICE WATER.
YOU SHOW UP WITH THE SUNGLASSES
ON, WE HAVE ISSUES.
JUST MIX THIS.
MORE WATER.
A LOT OF TIME
AND ENERGY, BRO.
KEEP ON TIGHTENING IT UP
AND LOOSENING IT UP
TO THE POINT WHERE IT JUST
CAN'T HOLD ANY MORE WATER.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THIS
IN MY LIFE.
IT IS DYING
FOR A TORTILLA CHIP.
I THINK RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S IT.
WOW.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
A PARTY.
THAT'S SO AWESOME. THAT'S GOT
THE RIGHT BALANCE OF FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT OVERLY FISHY.
IT'S NOT OVERLY SALTY.
IT'S ACTUALLY
FREAKING ME OUT.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS BEFORE.
I'M COMPLETELY AMAZED.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
OH, COME ON DOWN HERE TO POKE,
AND WE'RE GONNA HAVE SOME,
UH, SEAFOOD GAZPACHO.
KILLER SEAFOOD GAZPACHO.
I DIDN'T THINK I'D LIKE IT.
I LOVE IT.
(woman) O'IO!
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT IS AWESOME.
IT'S REALLY INTERESTING.
IT JUST TASTES REALLY FRESH.
TWO ORDERS OF FRIED MOI.
GENUINE HAWAIIAN FOOD.
EVERYTHING YOU'VE HAD
HERE HAS BEEN GOOD?
OH, EXCELLENT, YES.
THIS IS PHENOMENAL.
IT'S WHAT I WANT TO EAT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
THE EXPERIENCE HAS BEEN GREAT.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, NICE TO HEAR THAT
FROM YOU. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BEEN A PLEASURE, MAN.
GOTTA CHECK THIS GUY OUT.
THANK YOU.
NEXT UP...
THIS IS HOME COOKING.
WE'RE HEADING EAST
TO SOUTH CAROLINA...
THESE THINGS ARE HOT.
FOR GREENS...
THESE COLLARD GREENS
ARE GREAT.
AND GRITS.
MMM. GREAT.
DELICIOUS. FANTASTIC.
THIS IS ROUTE 1,
RIGHT BETWEEN
COLUMBIA, SOUTH CAROLINA,
AND AUGUSTA, GEORGIA,
IN A LITTLE TOWN ON THE CAROLINA
SIDE CALLED LEXINGTON.
NOW WHAT WE HAD HERE
WAS A FARMER'S MARKET,
AND THEN IT TURNED
INTO A GARDEN CENTER.
AND WHEN YOU HAVE
A GARDEN CENTER,
WHAT DO YOU ADD NEXT?
YEP, OF COURSE--
A RESTAURANT.
THIS IS THE FARMER'S SHED.
FRIED CHICKEN AND SUCCOTASH.
IT'S TYPICAL
SOUTHERN FOOD.
AND THEN VEGGIES.
MACARONI AND CHEESE,
COLLARD GREENS.
THIS IS HOME COOKING.
THIS IS WHAT I GREW UP WITH.
JUST LIKE SHIRLEY SEASE.
GOOD EVENIN'.
YOU GREW UP AS A FARMING
FAMILY'S DAUGHTER.
YEP, AND THEN
I MARRIED A FARMER.
MOVED FROM ONE FARM
TO ANOTHER FARM.
TO RUNNING THIS FARMER'S
MARKET, WHERE EIGHT YEARS AGO,
SHE STARTED COOKING
SOUTHERN CLASSICS
STRAIGHT FROM HER OWN FARM.
THESE COLLARD GREENS
ARE GREAT.
YOU GROW THESE
HERE ON YOUR FARM.
YES, YES.
I DON'T KNOW THAT
EVERYBODY IN THIS COUNTRY
REALLY APPRECIATES
GREENS.
THEY SHOULD.
SO WE GOT THESE ALL CHOPPED UP,
READY TO GO.
RIGHT.
AND THIS IS WHAT
THEY LOOK LIKE.
WANNA SEE THE DANCE I DO?
NO, WE DON'T
WANT TO SEE THAT.
FIRST THING I'M GONNA ADD
IS WATER.
I'LL PUT A HAM HOCK IN.
LOOK AT THAT.
SMOKED HAM HOCK.
YOU THINK I CAN SHOOT IT
FROM THE BACK?
DO YOU CLEAN UP
YOUR MESSES?
HEY!
YEAH.
I'LL ADD A LITTLE
CHICKEN BASE TO IT,
JUST TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE OOMPH,
THEN SOME BLACK PEPPER,
AND THEN SOME SALT.
AND WE'RE GONNA COOK THIS
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES,
UNTIL THE HAM HOCK...
COMES APART.
THEN WE'LL ADD
THE COLLARD GREENS.
FEEL LIKE I'M FEEDING
THE HORSES BACK IN FERNDALE.
POP A LID ON IT,
AND HOW LONG DO THEY COOK?
20 TO 25. THE COLLARDS
SHOULD BE READY.
WOW, LOOK HOW MUCH
THAT COOKS DOWN.
GOOD FOR YOU.
YEAH, THAT'S MY MOTTO, ALWAYS
EATING WHAT'S GOOD FOR ME.
OKAY.
AROUND HERE, UM,
YOU GOT--WE EAT HOT PEPPER
VINEGAR OVER OUR COLLARD GREENS.
OH, YEAH, AROUND HERE,
WE DO, TOO.
LIKE THAT?
MM-HMM.
GET ME SOME COLLARDS.
MMM, THOSE ARE TENDER,
SWEET.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
HOCK MEAT IN THERE.
MMM...
LOAD OF THAT HOT PEPPER
VINEGAR.
I COULD CHUG THAT.
MMM.
I'VE HAD GREENS
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
AND THESE RIGHT HERE
ARE SOME MONEY GREENS.
THOSE ARE WORTH
COMING TO TRY. MMM.
IF YOU DON'T THINK YOU
LIKE GREENS, COME EAT THESE.
AND THEN IF YOU DON'T
LIKE THESE,
WELL, THEN YOU WERE JUST NEVER
BLESSED ENOUGH TO LIKE GREENS.
I NEED A SIDE
OF COLLARDS.
SHE SEASONS 'EM WELL.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WITH THE HAM HOCK, IT JUST
MELTS THE FLAVORS TOGETHER. MMM.
THEY INTRODUCED ME
TO COLLARDS HERE,
AND NOW I HAVE
TO HAVE 'EM.
THAT'S PORK CHOP
ON THIS ONE.
I LIKE HOW THEY HAVE THE SAME
MENU ON CERTAIN DAYS.
SO EVERYBODY KIND OF HAS THEIR
DAY THAT THEY LIKE TO COME FOR?
I JUST WAIT FOR WEDNESDAYS,
'CAUSE ON WEDNESDAYS,
IT'S CHICKEN DAY.
IT'S WONDERFUL. MMM.
I THINK I WANT
THAT PIECE.
YOU WANT THAT PIECE.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
WHAT'S THE MOST
POPULAR DAY?
FRIDAY.
SHRIMP AND GRITS
WITH TASSO GRAVY.
I TRIED IT IN OTHER PLACES,
AND SHE HAS THE BEST.
OKAY, SO HOW DO WE
START HER OFF?
LET'S MAKE THE TASSO GRAVY.
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
IS BUTTER, THEN THE LEEKS.
WE'LL LET THESE JUST SWEAT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW--
WE'RE GOING TO ADD
OREGANO, BLACK PEPPER,
SOME FLORIDA BAY SEASONING,
PAPRIKA,
CHILI POWDER,
SOME GARLIC POWDER...
SEASONED SALT.
SEASONED SALT--YOU'RE GOOD.
BASIL...
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THYME.
OF FRENCH THYME.
OH!
(French accent) YOU KNOW...
AND A LITTLE TOMATO JUICE.
A LITTLE SIZZLE THERE.
CLAM JUICE...
(normal voice) OKAY.
NEXT, HALF-AND-HALF.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA GET
THE ROUX IN IT.
AND THEN WE JUST LET THAT
COME BACK TO A BOIL.
RIGHT NOW THERE'S
A MINI NIAGARA FALLS
GOING ON IN MY MOUTH.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THIS.
AND THIS IS TASSO HAM.
OH, YOU SAID,
"TRY SOME HAM"?
MMM, DELICIOUS.
AND WE'RE GONNA CUT THE HEAT
OFF, AND IT'S READY.
NOW WE'LL MAKE GRITS?
I LOVE GRITS.
GOOD, I DO, TOO.
LOCAL
STONE-GROUND GRITS...
SO LET'S GET INTO IT.
I'LL PUT THE WATER IN.
NEXT WE'LL ADD THE MILK,
THE STICK OF BUTTER,
JUST A LITTLE SALT.
WE'LL LET IT COME TO A BOIL,
THEN WE'LL ADD
THE GRITS.
JUST GOOD OL'
GRIT MAKING.
AND THOSE HAVE THICKENED UP.
(imitating "The Terminator")
I'M THE GRIT-O-NATOR.
YOU TRY MY GRITS.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THEM.
I PROMISE, YOU'LL BE BACK.
(normal voice) IS THAT
THE CONSISTENCY YOU WANT?
YES.
NOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SHRIMP.
WE'LL PUT SOME BUTTER.
I LOVE SOMEBODY
WHO COOKS WITH A HOT PAN.
GET 'ER GOIN'!
YEAH, THAT'S REALLY HOT.
HOW MANY SHRIMP?
ALL OF 'EM.
JUST COOK THOSE UP TILL
THEY GET A LITTLE BIT OF A--
A LITTLE PINK.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME TASSO GRAVY ON THEM.
WE'RE NOT USING
ALL THIS TASSO.
NO, WE'RE NOT,
'CAUSE WE'RE PUTTING IT
IN THE BACK OF A '67 CAMARO
THAT'S GOING BACK
TO CALIFORNIA!
OKAY, WANT ME
TO PUT SOME GRITS ON HERE?
SURE.
SO THE TASSO SAUCE
IS READY.
NOW CAN I HAVE
SOME OF THE, UH--
THOSE ARE CALLED
FIELD PEAS.
AND, UH, GREEN BEANS.
OKAY, LET'S TRY THIS.
MMM. THIS HAS EVERYTHING.
SOME SEAFOOD,
A LITTLE VEGGIE IN THERE.
A LITTLE BIT SPICY. MMM.
GRITS ARE PERFECTLY COOKED.
THANKS.
REAL TEXTURE TO 'EM,
BUT REAL CREAMINESS TO 'EM.
THIS TASSO AND SHRIMP--
THIS IS THE DICTIONARY
DEFINITION OF IT. MMM.
YOU CAN FIND THAT DICTIONARY
AT THE FLAVOR TOWN LIBRARY.
GREAT. DELICIOUS.
FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT,
I GOT A SHRIMP AND GRITS.
THE GRITS ARE WONDERFUL.
SMOOTH AND CREAMY,
AND THEY'RE THE YELLOW GRITS,
WHICH I LOVE. MMM.
I LOVE THE TASSO GRAVY.
REALLY BRINGS OUT
THE FLAVOR IN THE SHRIMP.
I LOOK FORWARD TO FRIDAYS
TO COME TO MISS SHIRLEY'S
AND GET SOME SHRIMP AND GRITS.
I LOVE THE FARMER'S SHED.
JEFFERSON CHICKEN.
THESE THINGS ARE HOT.
IT BEATS ANY OTHER
SOUTHERN COOKING AROUND HERE.
THIS IS LIKE SUNDAY DINNER
AT GRANNY'S HOUSE,
KICKED UP A NOTCH.
NOW YOU NEED
SOME CORNBREAD
TO GET THE POT--
WHERE'S THE CORNBREAD?
THAT'S COMING.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
AT THE FARMER'S SHED
IN LEXINGTON, SOUTH CAROLINA...
THESE THINGS ARE HOT.
THEY'VE GOT
A FARMER'S MARKET...
ALL RIGHT, GREEN BEANS,
ZUCCHINI SQUASH, MAC AND CHEESE.
AND A RESTAURANT.
I LOVE THEIR FOOD.
AND OWNER SHIRLEY SEASE
IS COOKING IT UP
STRAIGHT FROM THE FARM.
IT'S ALL FRESH.
KIND OF REMINDS YOU OF GRANDMA
COOKING SOMETHING ON THE FARM.
AND AROUND HERE,
THAT MEANS CORNBREAD...
I LOVE IT.
A FARMER'S SHED
FAMILY RECIPE.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA USE
SOME YELLOW CORNMEAL
THAT IS LOCALLY GROWN.
OH, OH!
SELF-RISING CORNMEAL,
SO THERE'S SOME LEAVENING
AGENTS ALREADY IN IT.
YES, AND SALT.
THAT'S A GOOD START
WE DID RIGHT THERE--
DIDN'T COME OUT
OF A BOX.
ADD SOME FLOUR
AND SOME SUGAR.
(whistles)
SEE? IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
MY SECRET INGREDIENT.
IT'S A SAVORY SPICE.
ALL RIGHT, THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
EIGHT EGGS IN THERE.
NOW MUCH MILK
ARE WE PUTTING IN?
MOST OF THIS.
WE'LL STIR IT AND SEE.
YOU'RE GAMBLING,
AREN'T YOU?
MM-HMM, STIR THIS UP.
IS THAT THE CREAMINESS
THAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR?
WE ARE RIGHT AT IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
IN A HOT SKILLET.
THAT SKILLET'S
DONE SOME TIME.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME...
BUTTER-FLAVORED OIL.
WE'RE GONNA FILL IT UP.
LOOK, IT'S ALREADY STARTING
TO FORM UP CRUST.
MM-HMM.
THAT PAN IS SO HOT RIGHT NOW,
YOU CAN'T--
MY HANDS FROM HERE--IT'S STILL
TOO HOT TO BE NEXT TO.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH SOME BROWN SUGAR.
NOW HOW LONG,
AND WHAT TEMPERATURE.
425...
(whistles)
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
CORNBREAD'S READY.
READY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOK AT THAT. SO
WHAT ARE THOSE OVER THERE?
WHAT?
OH, I GUESS NOTHIN'.
LOOK AT THE STEAM
COMIN' OFF THAT THING.
ALL RIGHT, LET ME GET
A PIECE OF THIS.
LIKE THAT CRUNCHY STUFF.
MMM, THAT TASTES GREAT
JUST BY ITSELF.
IT'S MOIST,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT TO IT.
MMM, SWEET.
SWEET.
I GET SOME OF THAT
BUTTER NOTE FROM IT,
FROM THAT BUTTERY OIL.
MMM.
I MEAN, THAT IS
SO SWEET ON THE TOP,
AND THAT LITTLE
SUGAR NUGGET I GOT,
THAT'S ALMOST LIKE
A DONUT OR A SCONE.
GREAT CORNBREAD. YOU CAN STAY
IN SOUTH CAROLINA NOW.
I WON'T GET RUN OUT.
NOPE, YOU'LL BE FINE.
GOOD OL' SOUTHERN COOKIN'
RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, AND HERE'S
YOUR CORNBREAD.
IT'S ALMOST CREAMY
FOR A BREAD.
THEY TAKE THE EXTRA TIME TO COOK
IT THE WAY IT NEEDS TO BE.
I FEEL LIKE I'M PART
OF SHIRLEY'S FAMILY
WHEN I'M SITTING HERE
EATING HER FOOD.
DID YOU ENJOY
THAT CHICKEN?
YES, MA'AM.
WELL, GOOD.
THEY JUST KIND OF
TAKE CARE OF EVERYBODY.
AND WHAT IS IT THAT YOU
LIKE MOST ABOUT THIS?
DEALING WITH THE PEOPLE
AND SERVING PEOPLE FOOD.
HOW ARE THE SHRIMP
AND GRITS TODAY?
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING.
I HAD SOME GREAT FOOD TODAY.
IT'S A NEAT EXPERIENCE.
FARMER'S MARKET,
GARDEN SHED--
OF COURSE--RESTAURANT.
GOOD JOB, GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
WHAT A GREAT ROAD TRIP.
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO CHECK OUT.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WELCOME TO
MULBERRY ITALIAN RISTORANTE.
(laughter)
HOW'D YOU LIKE THAT?