HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU COME FROM
LUCCA, ITALY.
LUCA FROM LUCCA.
BRINGIN' IT HOME...
(man) FUSILLI BOLOGNESE.
(woman) I CAN PRETEND
THAT I'M IN ITALY.
AND I LOVE THAT.
IN KENWOOD, CALIFORNIA,
THE LOCAL CAFé
DOIN' THE CLASSICS
(man) LINGUINI VONGOLE.
THEY BROUGHT HOME
FROM ITALY.
MMM.
IN CHARLOTTE...
TACOS ON THE GRILL.
THE TAQUERIA...
OH, YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
WHERE BRINGIN' IT HOME...
BEST TACO I'D EVER HAD.
MEANS DOIN' A CALIFORNIA
SPECIAL...
I'M HAVING THE BARBECUE
MAHI FISH TACO.
2,300 MILES AWAY.
NICE LITTLE BITE TO IT.
MMM.
AND IN HAWAII...
CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE
IN THE WINDOW.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD PUB...
WORLD CLASS.
WHERE THEY'RE BRINGING
IT HOME...
GAELIC STEAK.
FROM IRELAND.
MMM, THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
WANNA TRY SOME OF THIS?
NOT TODAY.
JUST KIDDING.
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP
RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE ON HIGHWAY 12
IN KENWOOD, CALIFORNIA,
IN THE HEART
OF THE TRUE WINE COUNTRY
ABOUT 8 MILES FROM MY HOME TOWN
OF SANTA ROSA
TO VISIT A LITTLE JOINT THAT
I'VE BEEN COMIN' TO FOR YEARS.
NOW THE FOOD'S FANTASTIC.
AND THE AMBIANCE, WELL,
IT'S PRETTY UNIQUE.
BUT THE REAL KICKER HERE
IS THE FAMILY.
LUCA, LINDA AND THE KIDS, WELL,
THEY'LL MAKE YOU FEEL
LIKE YOU'RE AT HOME.
THIS IS CAFE CITTI.
THANK YOU FOR COMING.
I LOVE THE PEOPLE.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
IT FEELS LIKE YOU'VE GOT
A PIECE OF ITALY RIGHT HERE
IN SONOMA COUNTY.
THANKS TO LUCA CITTI.
(Guy) YOU COME
FROM LUCCA, ITALY.
LUCA FROM LUCCA.
HOW'D YOU GET HERE?
THAT WAS MY WIFE.
THAT'D BE LINDA CITTI
A NOR-CAL LOCAL WHOSE MOTHER
GREW UP IN ITALY.
VERY GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING BRINGING HIM
BACK TO THE STATES?
WHAT ELSE?
PUTTIN' TOGETHER
THEIR FAMILY RECIPES...
MY MOTHER WAS A GREAT COOK.
HIS MOTHER'S A GREAT COOK.
AND DOIN' NORTHERN ITALIAN
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
LINGUINI WITH CLAM SAUCE.
JUST WONDERFUL.
(Luca) GNOCCHI AND PESTO.
THEIR HOMEMADE PASTAS
ARE ALWAYS GREAT.
LIKE THEIR NUMBER ONE SELLER.
(man) RAVIOLI ALLA CITTI.
MMM, IT'S GREAT.
(Luca) WE MAKE THIS
EVERY DAY.
(Guy) WAIT A SECOND.
YOU MAKE THE RAVIOLIS FRESH
EVERY DAY?
YES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME RAVIOLI FILLING.
SAUSAGE SALTED
WITH YELLOW ONIONS.
PUT THIS IN
THE BUFFALO CHOPPER.
BUFFALO CHOPPER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE CHARD.
BRAISED SWISS CHARD?
YEAH. NOW I'M GONNA PUT
SOME MILK TO THE BREAD.
THIS IS GONNA SOAK IT.
I'M GONNA START
THE BUFFALO CHOPPER NOW.
YOU START IT AWAY.
ONE EGG.
PEPPER, PARMESAN.
NUTMEG AND SALT.
NOW YOU GOT IT?
GREAT.
IT'S STILL GOT TEXTURE.
STILL GOT THE COLOR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GOSH! YOU COULD JUST SERVE IT
LIKE THIS TO PEOPLE.
NOW TO MAKE SOME RAVIOLIS.
THE FLOUR.
NINE EGGS.
NEXT, WINE.
AND THE WHITE WINE?
I DON'T KNOW THIS ONE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
OF ACIDITY.
SO THERE'S SOME LIFE
TO THE DOUGH.
NEXT, OLIVE OIL,
SALT.
ABOUT A TABLESPOON
AND A HALF.
THEN WATER.
YOU ONLY ADDED
ABOUT 1/4 CUP,
'CAUSE SO MUCH OF THE LIQUID
CAME FROM THE EGGS.
LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR IN THERE
RIGHT NOW SO IT STAYS
AS A BALL, DOESN'T GET TOO
TACKY. KNEAD IT A LITTLE BIT.
TO KEEP IT FROM DRYIN' OUT,
WRAP IT TIGHT.
GONNA LET IT REST
FOR ABOUT HALF AN HOUR?
YEP.
READY TO GO?
PERFECT. CUTTING IT.
FLATTEN IT OUT.
START ON THE BIGGEST DIAL FIRST.
FEED IT THROUGH ONE TIME.
YOU DON'T WANT TO MAKE IT GO
THROUGH TOO HARD,
BECAUSE THEN IT CHANGES
THE TEXTURE OF IT.
AND THEN YOU DROP DOWN
ABOUT TWO NOTCHES.
DON'T STRETCH
TOO HARD, YEAH.
FOLD IT OVER ONCE.
CREATES MORE TEXTURE
OF THE RAVIOLI BY MAKING IT
PRESS ITS LAYERS TOGETHER.
A LOT OF WORK JUST
TO MAKE RAVIOLIS.
BEAUTIFUL.
NOW WE'RE AT
THE RIGHT NUMBER.
AND NOW WE ADD
THE FILLING.
OKAY.
SO THIS LOOK WONDERFUL.
SPRAY A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
GOT A LITTLE WATER.
SO IT'LL STICK
TOGETHER NICE.
NOW WE SQUEEZE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE AIR OUT.
IF IT GETS AN AIR BUBBLE
IN LIKE THAT, IT CRACKS,
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT
AN OPEN RAVIOLI.
THEN GO ALL THE WAY DOWN.
500 A DAY?
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
I'LL PUT IT IN THE FREEZER
ONE NIGHT.
SO WHEN YOU COOK IT,
IT COOKS THE RIGHT WAY, RIGHT?
YES.
PUT IT IN
THE BOILING WATER.
WE'VE GOTTA PUT IN
SOME MARINARA SAUCE.
(Guy) SO YOU MAKE ALL
OF YOUR OWN SAUCES?
YEP.
YOU KEEP IT COLD AND JUST
HEAT IT UP AS YOU NEED IT.
EXACTLY. FRESH BASIL,
COUPLE LEAF.
PUT IT ON THE FIRE,
THEN A LITTLE BIT PEPPER.
THEN I ADD
THE HEAVY CREAM.
WHIPPING CREAM,
BUT WITHOUT THE SUGAR.
NICE LITTLE PINK SAUCE.
THERE WE GO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOKS GOOD TO ME.
COUPLE OF FLIP.
NIAGARA FALLS
IN MY MOUTH.
AND THERE WE GO.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY
JUST FOR LOOK.
GOOD OLD ITALIAN
PARSLEY.
YEAH, ITALIAN
PARSLEY ALWAYS.
OKAY. IT'S GOT GREAT COLOR.
(groans) THE PASTA
IS SO TENDER
THAT IT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE PORK IS GROUND
JUST TO THE RIGHT BIT
SO YOU GET THE TEXTURE
OF THE PORK. MMM.
IT'S AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVOR.
I DON'T THINK I COULD
ACTUALLY EAT MORE THAN FOUR.
MMM.
ONE LAST BITE. MAYBE
I COULD EAT MORE THAN FOUR.
I MEANT 14.
IT'S LIGHT AND FRESH.
IT'S REALLY AMAZING.
EVERYTHING'S JUST
VERY GOOD, VERY TASTY.
MAKE THE PIZZA, MAKE THE SAUCE,
MAKE THE FOCACCIA.
PIZZA PROSCIUTTO
MASCARPONE.
MMM.
CREAMY, SALTY AND CRUNCHY.
THAT'S IT.
BASICALLY, EVERYTHING HE
MAKES HERE IS HOMEMADE.
THE PESTO GNOCCHI
IS PROBABLY MY FAVORITE.
(man) LINGUINI VONGOLE.
CRISPY FRIED POLENTA
WITH THE OFF-THE-HOOK
PORCINI MUSHROOM SAUCE.
YEP, PORCINI MUSHROOMS...
PERFECT.
A STAPLE IN FLORENCE...
PORCINI MUSHROOMS.
THAT LUCA IS PICKING
IN SEASON RIGHT OUT BACK.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE,
BOSS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
POLENTA.
WE GOT SOME BOILING WATER,
SALTED.
I'M GONNA TURN IT OFF THE WATER.
JUST SLOWLY ADD THE POLENTA.
WHY SO SLOW?
IT'S NOT GONNA BECOME
COAGULATED.
SO IT DOESN'T COAGULATE.
COAGULATE. THAT'S WHY
WE TURN IT OFF.
OTHERWISE, IT WOULD BIND UP.
BIND UP.
PERFECT. NOW WE'RE GONNA
TURN ON THE HEAT AGAIN.
LET IT SIMMER?
LET IT SIMMER A LITTLE BIT.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CHEESE?
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
THE ONLY CHEESE, BABY.
AND THEN HOW MUCH BUTTER?
300 GRAMS WOULD BE FINE.
ABOUT A CUP OF BUTTER.
A LITTLE HEAVY CREAM?
YEP, LIKE A CUP
AND A HALF.
IT'S GOTTA COOK UNTIL
THE POLENTAS COME APART
FROM THE SIDE OF THE BOWL
LIKE THE PIZZA DOUGH.
YOU'LL SEE A LITTLE GAP BETWEEN
THE POLENTA AND THE SIDE.
SO ONCE THIS IS DONE,
OIL UP A SHEET TRAY.
POUR IT SLOWLY.
BE CAREFUL.
(whistles)
AND NOW WITH THIS
OILED SPATULA,
WE JUST FLATTEN IT UP
A LITTLE.
NICE AND EVEN.
PERFECT. LET IT COOL DOWN.
PUT IT IN THE WALK-IN.
THEN ONCE IT'S COOLED,
WE CAN CUT IT, FRY IT UP.
FRY IT UP,
BECAUSE THAT'S THE WAY
MY FAMILY USED TO DO IT.
AND THIS GOES
RIGHT TO THE FRYER.
POLENTA'S FRYING.
WHAT ARE WE PUTTIN' ON IT?
I'M GONNA DO A PORCINI
CREAM SAUCE.
A LITTLE BIT BUTTER.
A LITTLE BIT GARLIC.
THIS IS THE PORCINI.
MMM.
WE ALL SMELLED IT.
A LITTLE PINCH LIKE...
A LOT OF FLAVOR
THERE.
YEAH, I LOVE
PORCINIS THE BEST.
THE KING OF THE MUSHROOM,
I THINK. TOUCH PARSLEY.
WE WANT TO PUT IN
SOME MARSALA.
OH, A LITTLE MARSALA.
MMM.
AND THE CREAM.
REDUCE.
I LIKE WHERE THAT'S GOIN'.
A LITTLE PEPPER.
AW, THAT SMELLS GREAT.
LOOK WHAT WE GOT, HUH?
I THINK WE'RE READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE AND CRISPY, AND JUST POUR
THIS CREAM ALL OVER.
THERE WE GO.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
OKAY, PARMIGIANO?
MMM. SMELLS FANTASTIC.
DONE.
(chuckles)
WOW, WHAT A GREAT SAUCE.
NOT REALLY HEAVY. YOU THINK,
CREAM SAUCE--SUPER HEAVY.
THERE'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF CREAM IN THERE.
THIS, MY FRIEND,
IS BORDERING ON ILLEGAL.
AND I SAID "ILLEGAL," NOT
"ILL EAGLE," A SICK BIRD.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU, CHEF.
THE MUSHROOMS JUST
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE POLENTA--
SO CRISPY.
(man) FUSILLI BOLOGNESE.
I CAN PRETEND
THAT I'M IN ITALY
AND I LOVE THAT.
(woman) IT'S SO HOMEY,
YOU CAN'T STAND IT.
IT'S PERFECT.
PERFECT. I CAN'T GO TO ITALY,
SO I COME HERE.
I'M GLAD.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S WHAT WE
LIKE TO HEAR.
THANKS FOR LETTIN' US
COME IN AND, UH...
THANK YOU.
WE LOVE THE FOOD,
AND WE LOVE THE FAMILY.
THANK YOU, GUY.
OKAY?
WE LOVE YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADIN' EAST
TO CHARLOTTE...
I NEED A COMBO ROLL.
FOR TACOS...
THEY'RE SO AMAZING.
CALIFORNIA STYLE.
I NEED A HALF TUNA/
HALF MAHI.
YOU DEFINITELY NOTICE THE
FLAVORS. YOU GOT IT EVERYWHERE.
ON THE NORTHERN TIP
OF CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA,
IS A LITTLE NEIGHBORHOOD
KNOWN AS "NoDa,"
NORTH DAVIDSON ART DISTRICT,
AND THIS IS WHERE
ALL THE TEXTILE PLANTS AND MILLS
HAVE BEEN CONVERTED
INTO ART GALLERIES
AND RETAIL SHOPS AND APARTMENTS.
NOW ON THE CORNER
OF 35th AND NORTH DAVIDSON
IS A TACO SHOP THAT'S BECOME
A BIG PART OF THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
THIS IS CABO FISH TACO.
(man) I NEED A TAVARUA
TUNA TACO, MEDIUM-WELL.
A FISH TACO JOINT
IN NORTH CAROLINA?
I HAVE A FISH TACO
AND A BARBECUE MAHI TACO.
I'D NEVER HAD A FISH TACO
TILL I CAME HERE.
I NEED A HALF TUNA/HALF MAHI.
THEY'RE SO AMAZING.
TACOS ON THE GRILL.
LITERALLY THE BEST TACO
I'VE EVER HAD.
FROM VIRGINIA NATIVE
ROB CRENSHAW...
RASTA RIGHT HERE.
WHO GOT HOOKED ON FISH TACOS
WHILE SURFIN' IN CALI.
ALL THIS FOOD THAT NO ONE ELSE
REALLY HAD AROUND HERE.
BUT NOW THEY DO, AND HAVE
FOR MORE THAN EIGHT YEARS.
(Rob) BLACKENED TUNA, RARE!
SINCE HE AND HIS WIFE
MAEGHAN...
HOW ARE THE FISH TACOS?
OPENED THIS JOINT.
SHE DOES THE TABLES,
AND I DO THE COOKIN'.
FISH TACOS HIS WAY.
HOW ABOUT SOME BARBECUE?
I'M READY TO SELL BARBECUE.
(Guy) I DON'T THINK IT'S
THE FISH TACOS I'M USED TO
IN CALIFORNIA.
NOT AT ALL.
WE'RE IN NORTH CAROLINA.
I'M HAVING THE BARBECUE
MAHI FISH TACO.
WITH ROB'S OWN
MANGO BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
ON THE MAHI TO MAKE THE...
BARBECUE MAHI TACOS.
VERY NICE.
PUT THE FRESH MANGOES IN.
ROASTED RED PEPPERS.
YOU ROASTED THOSE
YOURSELF?
YEP. BALSAMIC VINEGAR.
WHITE VINEGAR.
I DO HAVE A LOCAL CHEF
THAT MAKES ALL MY SPICES.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH. RED PEPPER FLAKES.
CARIBBEAN JERK.
WHAT'D YOU CALL ME?
ADD THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
THAT YOU MAKE YOURSELF.
RIGHT.
WHAT'S IN
THE BARBECUE SAUCE?
KETCHUP, SPICES, VINEGAR.
IT'S PRETTY SIMPLE.
ONCE YOU GET ALL THAT
IN THERE, PULSE IT UP.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE
RIGHT NOW?
OUR VERSION
OF COLESLAW.
LET ME SEE THAT AGAIN.
THE WHOLE THING.
NOT WITH THE KNIFE!
CAREFUL OF THE KNIFE.
DEAD HOST, NO SHOW.
FIRST WHAT WE DO IS WE
CHOP GREEN CABBAGE UP.
NICE. THEN MAYONNAISE.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SLAW DRESSING.
YEP. LITTLE WHITE VINEGAR,
SUGAR.
AND WE USE A LITTLE
SEASONING SALT.
LIGHT CHILI POWDER,
DARK CHILI POWDER.
DIG IT.
CHOP UP CARROTS, CELERY,
WHITE ONIONS,
ROASTED RED PEPPERS,
GREEN PEPPERS.
AND YOU PREP THAT
AND PUT IT IN OTHER DISHES.
YES, A BUNCH OF DIFFERENT STUFF.
THAT ALL GOES IN.
I LIKE IT.
THEN THE KEY INGREDIENT--
CILANTRO.
AND THEN MIX IT
ALL UP.
NOW WHO CAME
UP WITH THIS RECIPE?
ME.
AND, UH, IT'S BEEN
TWISTED AND TURNED
OVER THE LAST NINE YEARS.
WE ADD THE CABBAGE.
AND THEN WE USUALLY LET
THIS SET UP 24 HOURS.
SOAK IT UP
A LITTLE.
LOOKS GREAT. I'M GONNA
AT LEAST TRY IT.
NICE LITTLE BITE TO IT.
ON-POINT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
BARBECUED MAHI TACOS.
START WITH 2 6-INCH
FLOUR TORTILLAS.
FIVE SECONDS. FLIP 'EM.
IT'S LIKE FLASH-FRYING 'EM.
NOT VERY LONG.
SO YOU USE FLOUR,
NOT CORN?
I THINK IT TASTES BETTER.
WHOA. REALLY?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE MAHI.
START WITH A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL ON THE FLAT TOP.
A LITTLE MAHI ON THE GRILL.
COMES IN FRESH,
AND YOU BUTCHER IT YOURSELF.
YEP. PUT MY BLACKENING
SEASONING.
GREAT.
I'M JUST GONNA WHIP
IT AROUND. ALL RIGHT.
SO WHILE THAT'S COOKIN',
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR TWO SHELLS.
ADD FRESH GUACAMOLE
WITH THE CHEESE.
A LITTLE BIT OF TOMATOES.
COLESLAW NEXT.
THAT LOOKS LIKE THAT'S
SOFTENED UP A LOT.
WALK BACK TO OUR GRILL.
COVER. WE MAKE OUR OWN
VEGETABLE STOCK,
AND I USE THOSE
FOR STEAM.
SO YOU PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GRILL ON IT.
THAT STEAM RIGHT THERE WILL
FINISH THE COOKING PROCESS.
AS SOON AS THAT MOISTURE PRETTY
MUCH GOES AWAY,
I SHRED IT, GRAB
THE MANGO BARBECUE SAUCE,
PUT IT ALL OVER IT,
TURN THIS INTO MAHI BARBECUE.
SO EACH ORDER IS MADE FRESH.
NOTHING'S HELD.
NO HEATING LAMPS HERE.
AND I GRAB THIS MAHI.
YOU REALLY HAVE
SOME NICE, FIRM FISH,
BUT IT'S NOT OVERCOOKED.
EXACTLY.
PLATE THESE GUYS UP, AND THEN
THE CILANTRO WHITE SAUCE.
A LOT GOING ON FOR
JUST A SIMPLE TACO.
BLACK BEANS AND RICE.
WE HAVE OUR CORN SALSA.
GONNA NEED A NAPKIN
FOR THIS ONE, "BIG DOGGY."
THERE'S A TON OF FLAVOR.
I MEAN, A TON OF FLAVOR.
THE FISH IS COOKED REALLY NICE.
THE SLAW BY ITSELF
HAS HUGE FLAVOR.
THE WHITE SAUCE--HUGE FLAVOR.
THAT MANGO BARBECUE SAUCE
IS ON-POINT.
RICE IS NICE AND FIRM.
YOU GO FROM DRY BEAN?
YEAH, DRY BEAN.
MMM, IT'S GOOD, BROTHER.
I NEED FOUR MANGO
BARBECUE TACOS.
A LITTLE BIT SPICY.
CABBAGE GIVES IT
SOME CRUNCH.
THE WHOLE THING
IS JUST PHENOMENAL.
EYE-ROLLING GOOD.
PRETTY MUCH
THE WHOLE MENU IS GREAT.
I NEED A CABO ROLL.
YOU DEFINITELY NOTICE
THE FLAVORS.
YOU GOT IT EVERYWHERE.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE IN
CHARLOTTE THAT YOU CAN FIND
FOOD LIKE THIS. THIS IS
THE CABO ROLL. MMM. OH, YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD.
CRAB DIP MEETS
AVOCADO SPRING ROLL.
HONEY WASABI
TUNA BURRITO!
WASABI TUNA BURRITO--
PERFECT EVERY TIME.
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE
THEIR WASABI SAUCE.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
HONEY WASABI SAUCE.
FIRST WE START WITH
SOME WASABI POWDER.
I KIND OF JUST LOOSEN IT
UP A LITTLE BIT.
THEN ICE-COLD WATER, RIGHT?
GET THAT INTO A PASTE...
(speaking indistinctly)
JUST THROW A LITTLE BIT
OF RED PEPPER FLAKES IN IT.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD THE HONEY
TO OUR HONEY WASABI,
AND ADD SOME MAYONNAISE.
YOU LOVE THAT MAYONNAISE,
DON'T YOU?
TWIST THIS ALL TOGETHER.
THAT'LL BE TASTY.
MMM.
I'M TAKIN' THAT ONE HOME.
SIMPLE, CREAMY, SPICY,
OH.
PUT A LITTLE OIL
ON MY FLAT TOP.
GRAB SOME OF MY NICE,
PRETTY TUNA.
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKING TUNA.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLACKENING SPICE.
SQUEEZE A LITTLE LEMON.
MIX IT AROUND.
THIS DOESN'T TAKE LONG,
SO WE'LL LET THAT COOK.
FLOUR 12-INCH TORTILLA.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL START WITH
A LITTLE RICE, A LITTLE CHEESE.
DIG IT.
TOMATOES, HOMEMADE
VEGGIE PURéE CONCOCTION.
LOVE THAT.
THEN THE MUSHROOMS,
THEN OUR HONEY WASABI SAUCE.
THE VEGGIE BURRITOS
MUST ROCK HERE.
THEY DO.
A LITTLE BIT LONGER.
DRENCH WITH
VEGGIE STOCK.
LET THAT STEAM
FOR JUST A SECOND.
ONLY TAKES ABOUT A MINUTE
AND A HALF, TWO MINUTES TOTAL.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S ALL COLORED UP.
MEDIUM-RARE? MEDIUM?
UNLESS THE CUSTOMER
WANTS IT RARE OR WELL-DONE,
RIGHT ABOUT MEDIUM-RARE.
COOL.
GONNA ROLL MY BURRITO JUST
LIKE THAT AND GRAB MY PAN.
THROW IT DOWN HERE
IN MY OVEN, 500 DEGREES.
THREE MINUTES.
WE CUT 'EM IN HALF.
THIS IS OUR MANGO-PINEAPPLE
SALSA RICE.
AND THAT'S THE GAME PLAN?
THAT'S IT.
TRY THAT.
THE FISH, MAN, BY ITSELF
IS OUTSTANDING.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
STILL NICE AND FLAKY AND MOIST,
AND YOU GET
THE MELTED CHEESE,
THE WARM TORTILLA
TOGETHER WITH IT?
I'LL DO THAT ALL DAY LONG.
THE HONEY WASABI SAUCE
IS ABSOLUTELY WHAT TIES
IT ALL TOGETHER.
JUST ENOUGH HEAT, BUT THEN YOU
GET THE BACK SIDE OF THE SWEET
RIGHT AT THE SAME TIME.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANKS.
I NEED A HONEY WASABI,
GOING WITH THE WASABI.
(woman) IT'S EXCELLENT.
I LOVE THE FISH, AND I LIKE
THAT SWEET, SAUCY-SASSY
THAT THE WASABI ADDS TO IT.
(woman)
SPICY, YUMMY.
KIND OF GAVE A LITTLE KICK
TO IT. IT'S VERY GOOD.
(woman) WHEN I WAKE IN
THE MORNING AND I KNOW
I'M HAVING A FISH TACO,
I'M EXCITED ALL DAY.
IT'S SOMETHING
TO LOOK FORWARD TO.
I GOTTA TELL YOU.
THAT'S ONE THING
THAT I REALLY LIKED ABOUT THIS
IS EVERYTHING THAT YOU BRING IN
YOU MAKE ON YOUR OWN.
GREAT JOB.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
TAKE IT EASY.
NEXT UP...
MEDIUM-RARE IN THE WINDOW.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO HAWAII...
THEY POUR THE BEST
PINT OF GUINNESS.
FOR SHAMROCKS...
I'M STARTIN' TO FROTH UP
A LITTLE BIT.
AND SHEPHERD'S PIE.
THE PORK THAT GOT MIXED
IN THERE WORKS WELL.
HERE I AM.
HONOLULU, HAWAII,
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM PIER 13
AND RIGHT ON THE CORNER
OF CHINATOWN,
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT HAS ONE
OF THE FIRST LIQUOR LICENSES
EVER OFFERED ON THE ISLAND
BACK IN 1874.
AND GET THIS--THE BUILDING'S
FROM THE 1890s.
WELCOME TO MURPHY'S
BAR AND GRILL.
WHAT CAN I GET YOU GUYS?
(man) UH, A GOOSE-PINEAPPLE.
I JUST WANTED TO BE
IN THE BAR BUSINESS.
SO DON MURPHY BOUGHT
THIS LOCAL LANDMARK
MORE THAN 22 YEARS AGO.
KEEP US BUSY.
AND THEN HE GOT HUNGRY.
MEDIUM-RARE
IN THE WINDOW.
IF THE "MURPH" LIKES TO EAT IT
THEN IT MAKES IT ON THE MENU.
THINGS I LIKE TO EAT.
FROM SALADS...
CAESAR WITH
THE BLACKENED AHI.
TO BURGERS.
ONE OF THEIR CLASSIC
SIGNATURES HERE AT MURPHY'S.
SO'S THIS.
OPEN-FACED TURKEY SANDWICH.
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
SO, MURPH, WHAT ARE WE WORKIN'
ON? CRANBERRY SAUCE?
FOR THE OPEN-FACED
TURKEY LEG SANDWICH.
HIT IT, DUDE.
HIT IT? ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER, SUGAR,
CRANBERRIES.
CINNAMON STICK.
LITTLE, UH, ORANGE ZEST.
SPLASH OF ORANGE JUICE.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S IT.
LET IT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER?
YEP.
OKAY, AND THIS IS GONNA
GO ON TOP OF THE TURKEY LEG.
EXACTLY.
UH, WHAT ARE WE DOIN' NOW?
WE'RE GONNA CUT THE TURKEY
LEGS OFF OF THIS TURKEY.
SO THE BONE'S NOT GONNA
MAKE IT IN THERE, RIGHT?
NO.
I THINK TURKEY LEG'S
A VERY GOOD CHOICE.
IT'S GOT SOME NICE TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF FAT TO IT.
SO YOU GET THE THIGH,
THE LEG, WINGS, TOO?
WINGS, TOO.
THE WHOLE THING
ALL GONNA GO ON HERE.
WE USUALLY COOK
TWO AT A TIME.
PUT ON A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
SALT AND PEPPER,
MORE OF YOUR THYME.
YOU AND THAT THYME.
DO YOU HAVE A THYME GARDEN?
NO.
YOU BEEN DOIN' TIME
WITH THYME?
CARROTS AND ONIONS.
CELERY UNDERNEATH THERE.
AND WE'RE GONNA SIT THERE
AND JUST ROAST IT ALL?
ABOUT, OH, AN HOUR 45,
2 HOURS.
THE CONVECTION OVEN
THAT NEVER STOPS.
THAT'S IT.
NOW IT COMES OUT.
YOU COOL IT DOWN.
SOMEONE SHREDS IT ALL OFF
AND MAKES UP SANDWICHES?
YOU GOT IT.
ARE WE GONNA HIT
ANY GRAVY ON THIS?
OH, YEAH, WE'LL HIT
SOME GRAVY.
AND YOU MAKE THIS
FROM THE STOCK?
YEP.
DID I DO SOMETHING WRONG?
(laughs)
I FORGOT.
I MEAN, I--
YOU'RE ON MY DIET.
YOU THINK I GOT THIS
BY RUNNIN' HERE?
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME OF THE CRANBERRY SAUCE.
THIS IS THANKSGIVING
SANDWICH, BROTHER.
THIS IS IT.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M GONNA LET
THE SHOVEL FEST BEGIN.
MMM.
THAT'LL SET YOU FREE, HUH?
WOW, YOU DIDN'T HIT
PLYMOUTH ROCK.
YOU DROVE RIGHT UP ON IT.
(laughs)
THE TURKEY'S ROASTED
PERFECTLY.
THIS IS COOKED DOWN, RENDERED
DOWN. ALL THE FAT'S OUT.
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
MMM.
THEN YOU MAKE THE GRAVY
OUT OF THE BONES,
WHICH IS THE ONLY WAY
TO PLAY BALL.
AND THEN YOU MAKE THIS REALLY
TANGY, TRUE CRANBERRY SAUCE.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD NIGHT FOOD
RIGHT THERE.
NICE JOB.
OPEN-FACE TURKEY.
I LOVE THE CRANBERRY.
THAT MIXTURE OF SAVORY
AND SWEET.
TASTES VERY FRESH,
VERY MOIST, AND TENDER.
IT'S ALL REAL.
FROM SCRATCH-MADE SIDES
TO HOMEMADE PIES...
OOZING BLUEBERRIES.
AND REAL IRISH CLASSICS.
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED, UH,
CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE.
WORLD-CLASS.
(Don) CERTAINLY WASN'T
GONNA BE ITALIAN
WITH THE LAST NAME
OF MURPHY.
BLACK AND TAN.
(woman) THEY POUR
THE BEST PINT OF GUINNESS
THAT YOU WILL FIND
IN HAWAII.
REALLY?
YOU SHOULD WATCH
ONE OF THE BARTENDERS
POUR YOU A PINT.
I'M STARTIN' TO FROTH UP
A LITTLE BIT THERE.
IT FEELS LIKE
A REAL IRISH PUB.
FROM TAP TO TABLE...
FISH-AND-CHIPS.
I GOT THE FISH-AND-CHIPS
TODAY. FANTASTIC.
AND MURPH'S OWN GAELIC STEAK...
I GOT THE RECIPE
OVER IN IRELAND, ACTUALLY.
IT'S JUST A REALLY
WELL-COOKED STEAK
WITH A NICE, UM, CREAMY
PEPPERCORN SAUCE.
WHAT ARE WE
MAKIN' NOW?
TODAY WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME GREEN PEPPERCORN SAUCE
FOR OUR GAELIC STEAK.
FIRST A LITTLE WHIPPING CREAM,
LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
A LITTLE BEEF BASE?
A LITTLE BEEF BASE.
AND YOU WANT ME TO DROP
THE PEPPERCORNS?
YOU CAN GO RIGHT AHEAD
AND DO THAT, IF YOU WOULD.
OKAY, SO LET THIS SIMMER DOWN
TILL THOSE PEPPERCORNS
OPEN UP A LITTLE BIT. THAT
BRINGS SOME OF THE FLAVOR OUT.
EXACTLY.
AND THAT'LL GO ON TOP
OF THE STEAK.
EXACTLY.
OKAY, SO,
UH, NEW YORK STEAK.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
ON THE GRILL.
CHOICE?
YEP. LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER.
HOW WE LOOKIN'?
LOOKIN' GREAT.
SO DO IT UP MEDIUM-RARE
AND THEN HIT THE PEPPERCORN
SAUCE ON TOP. DIG IT.
YOU GOT IT.
READY?
ALL RIGHT.
THEN A LITTLE BIT OF THE GAELIC
SAUCE THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
(speaking indistinctly)
(laughs)
IT'S LIKE HE'S SAVIN' SOME
FOR HIM.
THERE YOU GO.
FLOAT THAT BOAT.
MMM. THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
COOKED NICE AND MEDIUM-RARE.
THE PEPPERCORNS JUST
KIND OF POP OPEN.
MMM, I THINK WHAT REALLY
MAKES THAT ONE
IS THAT WORCESTERSHIRE KICK
THAT YOU THROW IN THERE.
OH, THAT'S GREAT, MAN.
YOU COULD PUT
THAT ON THAT...
(laughs)
IT WOULD TASTE GOOD.
WATCH THIS.
YOU WANT TO TRY SOME OF THIS?
NOT TODAY.
JUST KIDDING.
THERE YOU GO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
AW. GOOD CAMERA. GOOD
JOB. THANK YOU, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
GAELIC.
GREEN PEPPERCORN
IN THERE
GIVES IT A LITTLE BIT
OF SPICE.
THE SAUCE
IS JUST WONDERFUL.
(Guy) THE STAKE'S COOKED
THE RIGHT WAY?
MM-HMM.
BRINGS IT TOGETHER
WITH THE MASHED POTATOES.
AND THEY'RE HOMEMADE
MASHED POTATOES,
WHICH IS THE ONLY WAY TO GO.
WITH THE GAELIC STEAK
OR ON MURPH'S HOMEMADE
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
YOU'RE IN HONOLULU.
YOU'RE SURROUNDED BY SEAFOOD.
AND YOU'RE HAVING
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
EXACTLY.
WHEN I CAME TO HAWAII,
THIS WASN'T NECESSARILY
WHAT I THOUGHT I WAS
GONNA BE HAVING.
I'LL BET.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
AT MURPHY'S BAR AND GRILL
IN HONOLULU, HAWAII...
(woman) GAELIC STEAK.
OWNER DON MURPHY
IS DOIN' THE IRISH PUB
THING FOR REAL...
CORNED BEEF AND CABBAGE
IN THE WINDOW.
FROM PINTS...
THEY POUR THE BEST
PINT OF GUINNESS.
TO PLATES.
SHEPHERD'S PIE UP.
REALLY GOOD. MMM.
GONNA MAKE THE VEGETABLES
FOR THE SHEPHERD'S PIE.
OKAY.
SAUTé THEM.
GET SOME OIL DOWN.
GET A LITTLE ONIONS,
A LITTLE PARSNIP...
OKAY.
A LITTLE CARROTS,
A LITTLE CELERY.
CELERY.
MUSHROOMS, A BIT OF THYME.
THAT IS A LITTLE
LITTLE BIT OF THYME.
WE'LL PUT A LITTLE
BIT MORE LATER.
OKAY, SO WE SAUTé
THE VEGGIES DOWN.
NOW WE ADD THE PEAS.
KNOW WHAT WE CALL THAT?
"PEAS OUT."
PEAS OUT.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE DONE?
YEP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN THE BOAT.
LIKE, "ROW, ROW, ROW"?
"ROW, ROW, ROW."
NOW WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS
BONELESS LEG OF LAMB,
BRUSH IT UP WITH SOME OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
THEN WE'RE GONNA INSERT
SOME GARLIC IN HERE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE ROSEMARY...
KINDA THREAD IT UP
UNDERNEATH THERE.
AND JUST DRESS IT AROUND.
TOUGH TO FIND FRESH HERBS
HERE ON THE ISLAND?
NO, GREAT HERBS FROM
THE ISLAND HERE.
THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA SPRINKLE
A LITTLE THYME
OVER IT AS WELL.
PUT IT ON THE ROASTING RACK,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
AND HOW LONG WE GONNA
ROAST THIS OFF FOR?
ABOUT AN HOUR 45.
350?
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT
UNDER THAT, ACTUALLY.
(whistles)
(shouting)
SHE'S A QUIET ONE!
(laughs)
(normal voice) SO WE'LL LET
THESE REST A LITTLE BIT?
NOW WE'LL CUT THE, UH,
STRING OFF.
DIG IT.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
CUT IT UP IN CUBES.
LOOK AT THAT PIECE RIGHT THERE
WITH THE GARLIC.
THAT BITE'S NOT
GONNA BE GOOD.
MMM. YEP, GLAD I GOT THAT
OUT OF SOMEBODY'S WAY.
CUBE HER UP
KIND OF BITE-SIZE.
WHEN I CAME TO HAWAII,
THIS WASN'T NECESSARILY WHAT I
THOUGHT I WAS GONNA BE HAVIN'.
I'LL BET.
(chuckles)
OKAY, SO IS THAT ENOUGH
TO GO IN ONE DISH?
OH, PLENTY.
THEN WE JUST ADD SOME IN,
PUT A LITTLE REDUCED BEEF BASE
WITH A LITTLE PORT IN IT
RIGHT ON TOP.
A LITTLE THYME ON TOP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT YOUR
MASHED POTATOES ON HER.
THERE WE GO.
NOW YOU GOT
SOME MASHED POTATOES.
NOW YOU CAN POP THAT IN
THE OVEN AND LET IT BROWN UP?
READY?
THAT'S A LOT OF MASHED
POTATOES THERE, BOSS.
YOU SELL A LOT OF THIS?
QUITE A BIT.
THE LAMBS NICE.
I THINK THAT'S THE TREAT--
ROASTING THE LAMB,
COOKING IT SLOW,
THE ROSEMARY AND THE GARLIC,
AND THE PORT
THAT GOT MIXED IN THERE, THAT
LITTLE SUBTLETY WORKS WELL.
GOOD.
THANK YOU.
A LOT OF MASH.
THAT'S THE WAY YOU DO IT.
HERE'S YOUR
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
YOU'RE IN HONOLULU.
YOU'RE SURROUNDED
BY SEAFOOD,
AND YOU'RE HAVING
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
EXACTLY.
MAKES SENSE TO ME.
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
(woman) MY PARENTS
ARE IRISH,
SO IT'S A TASTE
OF HOME FOR ME. MMM.
(man) EVERYBODY YOU TALK
TO WHO'S FROM HAWAII
KNOWS ABOUT MURPHY'S.
TURKEY "JALA"
AND A FISH-AND-CHIPS.
IF IT'S NOT MURPHY'S,
IT'S JUST NOT LUNCH.
"IF IT'S NOT MURPHY'S,
IT'S JUST NOT LUNCH."
I'M NOT GOIN' OUT.
I'D MAKE A COMMERCIAL
OUT OF THAT.
HOW WE DOIN'?
GOOD, HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD, GOOD, GOOD.
IT'S GOOD FUN.
IT'S OUR LIFE. YOU KNOW,
IT'S 22 YEARS, AND I DON'T KNOW
THAT I COULD DO
ANYTHING ELSE.
DO YOU SURF?
NO.
PADDLE? FLOAT?
BRAISE? BURN?
DRINK.
GOT IT.
BINGO.
(laughs)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN'
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
WHAT DOES IT SAY
ON THE MENU RIGHT THERE?
(laughter)
(speaking indistinctly)
IT SAID "FREE FRIES."