HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
FOR A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IT'S THE KANSAS CITY
BARBECUE TOUR.
(Guy) AND WE'RE 'QUEing IT UP
ALL OVER TOWN...
WHOA!
LOOK AT THE CRAZY COLOR
IN THIS.
AT SMOKIN' GUNS...
BRISKET TUB.
WORLD-CLASS BRISKET...
(woman) THIS IS
COMPETITION-WORTHY.
COMPETITION-WORTHY
AT A RESTAURANT.
AND A KANSAS CITY SIGNATURE...
BURNT END PLATE.
THAT'D BE
IN MY TOP THREE.
AT RJ'S...
PORK SLAB.
WHERE A FRENCH CHEF...
FULL BABY BACK
COMING UP.
IS DOING RIBS...
LAMB RIBS.
YEAH. YEAH.
HIS WAY...
MMM. OH, MAN.
AT JOHNNY'S...
TWO HALF CHICKEN DINNERS
COMING UP.
WHERE THEIR
BARBECUED CHICKEN...
WE'RE GONNA DROP IT
IN HERE.
NO.
YES.
GETS A RIDE IN THE FRYER...
THAT'S FUNKY.
AND AT
THE 97-YEAR-OLD WOODYARD...
BABY BACK RIBS.
A KANSAS CITY CLASSIC.
MMM. BROTHER,
THOSE RIBS ARE KNOCKOUT.
I JUST ATE 20 POUNDS
OF PORK.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON THE KANSAS CITY
BARBECUE TOUR.
♪♪
NOW YOU KNOW I DIG BARBECUE,
SO YOU KNOW I GOT TO DIG
THIS TOWN--KANSAS CITY.
NOW ON THIS TOUR, I'M GONNA TAKE
YOU TO SOME OF THE PLACES
YOU'D DRIVE RIGHT BY
IF YOU DIDN'T HAVE
THE TRIPLE "D" INSIDE TRACK,
LIKE THIS ONE
IN NORTH KANSAS CITY'S
INDUSTRIAL DISTRICT.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKING OVER 14
YEARS OF COMPETITION BARBECUE,
OVER 400 AWARDS
AND ONE KILLER BRISKET.
THIS IS SMOKIN' GUNS BBQ.
BRISKET TUB.
HOW IS THAT BRISKET?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
HALF SLAB OF RIBS.
(woman) THIS IS
COMPETITION-WORTHY.
COMPETITION-WORTHY
AT A RESTAURANT...
IN A RESTAURANT.
IS ALMOST UNHEARD OF.
BUT NOT FOR PHIL HOPKINS...
HALF A SLAB OF BABYS UP.
AND HIS WIFE LINDA...
THANK YOU.
WHO'VE BEEN
TAKING HOME TROPHIES
FOR MORE THAN 13 YEARS.
THE BIGGEST ONE WE'VE WON
IS THE JACK DANIEL'S IN 1999,
THE WORLD CHAMPIONSHIP.
LET'S JUST TAKE A MOMENT.
I MEAN, THAT'S--
THAT'S HUGE, BROTHER.
AND THEIR BIGGEST WINNER...
BRISKET TO GO.
IS THEIR BIGGEST SELLER.
DEFINITELY A TEN,
NO QUESTION.
DEFINITELY A TEN.
BRISKET SANDWICH.
FULL OF FLAVOR.
STARTING WITH
THEIR AWARD-WINNING RUB.
OKAY, TELL US WHAT IT IS.
SALT, SUGAR,
BROWN SUGAR.
NOW WAIT A SECOND. THIS ISN'T
JUST REGULAR BROWN SUGAR.
IT'S A BROWN SUGAR
THAT'S BEEN DRIED IN THE OVEN
AND PUT IN
THE FOOD PROCESSOR,
SO NOW IT'S MORE OF A POWDER
WITH A LITTLE GRANULE IN IT.
THAT'S LIKE C.I.A.
BARBECUE RIGHT THERE.
PAPRIKA, CHILI POWDER,
CUMIN, WHITE PEPPER,
SOME BLACK PEPPER...
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
CAYENNE, GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER,
A LITTLE AC'CENT,
IT'S A FLAVOR ENHANCER.
OKAY.
AND THEN I'M GONNA
LET YOU KNOW WHAT THE TWO
THAT NOBODY HAS EVER GUESSED
IN TEN YEARS.
THE TWO INGREDIENTS
THAT NO ONE'S EVER GUESSED.
CAN I GUESS?
YEAH, SURE.
CINNAMON AND CLOVE?
YOU WERE RIGHT ON
WITH THAT ONE.
THANK YOU.
THAT WAS CINNAMON.
NOW THIS IS ALLSPICE
OR GINGER OR NUTMEG OR...
COCOA.
YOU'RE GOING TO TELL ME
THAT THAT AMOUNT OF COCOA
WILL MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
WAIT TILL YOU TASTE IT.
AND THE MORE YOU STIR THIS,
THE MORE IT'LL BRING THE OIL
OUT, AND YOU GET A BETTER COLOR.
ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S GRAB
ONE OF THOSE BRISKETS.
WHAT SIZE ARE WE GONNA USE?
AROUND 16.
WOW.
I'M GONNA TRIM IT REAL LIGHTLY,
SKIN THE FAT OFF OF IT,
JUST SO I CAN GET SOME SEASONING
DOWN TO THAT MEAT.
SEE HIM RUN THAT KNIFE
LIKE A SURGEON?
WE'RE GONNA APPLY
SOME OF THIS RUB.
AND WHAT ARE
WE SMOKING THIS ON?
A COMBINATION OF OAK,
HICKORY AND CHERRY.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
NOW WHAT WE HAVE HERE--
HOW LONG HAVE YOU HAD THIS?
EIGHT YEARS.
GOT YOUR MONEY OUT OF THIS,
DIDN'T YOU?
YEP.
OKAY, BRISKET GOES DOWN, 225.
9 TO 11 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT, NOW AS LONG
AS I'VE BEEN DOING BARBECUE,
COMPETING WITH MOTLEY QUE,
ONE GUY THAT'S BEEN
KIND OF LIKE A MENTOR,
ONE DUDE THAT I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
ABLE TO LOOK AT,
ASK THE GOOD BARBECUE QUESTIONS
TO--DOCTOR BARBECUE, RAY LAMPE.
I'M ALWAYS HAPPY TO COME OUT
AND TEST SOME BARBECUE.
I KNOW YOU ARE.
LET'S SEE WHAT HE'S GOT.
LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL. MAN, THAT'S WHAT
IT'S SUPPOSED TO LOOK LIKE.
NOW WE'LL LET IT REST.
HOW LONG?
15 MINUTES.
15 "I WANT TO PICK AT IT
AND EAT SOME OF IT" MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW I'LL SKIM OFF ANY FAT
THICKER THAN A 1/4 OF AN INCH.
VERY NICE.
HOW THICK
DO YOU LIKE YOURS?
PENCIL THICK, JUST LIKE
I WAS AT A CONTEST.
NOW, RAY, I'M UNDER
THE IMPRESSION
THAT YOU SHOULD BE ABLE
TO PULL IT LIGHTLY,
IT SHOULD COME APART.
EXACTLY.
STRETCHINESS, THAT'S WHAT YOU
WANT, BUT IT HAS TO COME APART.
OKAY, PUT IT ON
THE SANDWICH.
SEE, THE OUTSIDE, THAT BARK,
THAT'S WHERE ALL THE FLAVOR IS.
NICE, NOT DRY.
BEAUTIFUL.
THAT RUB, DUDE, FANTASTIC.
I'D RISK LIFE AND LIMB
FOR SOME MORE OF THAT.
THIS IS WHAT THE FOLKS
IN KANSAS CITY WANT.
THAT'S JUST PERFECT.
BRISKET.
HOW IS IT?
FANTASTIC.
VERY SMOKY, TENDER.
ORDER UP.
EVERY BITE THAT YOU TAKE
IS INCREDIBLY GOOD.
AND IF THAT AIN'T ENOUGH,
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE,
WE'RE ONLY HALFWAY HOME.
BURNT ENDS IS MY FAVORITE.
BURNT END PLATE.
THAT'S THE EPITOME
OF BRISKET.
OKAY, THAT'S BRISKET
THAT'S BEEN ON FOR 12 HOURS.
MAN.
WE'LL SEPARATE THE POINT
FROM THE FLAT...
RIGHT.
SO WE CAN GET MORE SPICE
DOWN TO THAT POINT.
RESEASON IT.
PUT IT BACK ON FOR
4 HOURS AT 225.
TIME TO PULL 'EM.
YEP.
LET'S DO IT.
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO NOW
IS CUT IT INTO CHUNKS.
WHEN I SPLIT THAT POINT OFF
THE FLAT, I KEPT THE AU JUS,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME RUB
TO THAT AU JUS
AND PUT THOSE BURNT ENDS
RIGHT BACK IN THERE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
RIGHT BACK ON THE PLATE.
NOW THAT'S A KANSAS CITY
BURNT END RIGHT THERE.
IS THAT HOW IT COMES?
THAT'S HOW WE SERVE IT.
I'VE HAD SOME BURNT ENDS
IN MY DAY.
THAT'D BE
IN MY TOP THREE.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS WHAT THE BARBECUE MAN
WOULD HAVE SAVED FOR HIMSELF.
OH, YEAH.
THIS IS THE PART
THE CHEF'S GONNA EAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF JUS,
PERFECT FINISH.
NOT TOO SWEET,
NOT TOO SALTY,
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
YOU HAVE GOT TO TRY
SOME OF THIS. EXCELLENT.
BURNT END PLATTER UP.
THEY'RE REAL TENDER,
AND THEY'RE JUST PERFECT.
BURNT ENDS,
POTATO CASSEROLE.
DEEP, SMOKY,
JUST THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
HALF A CHICKEN
WITH FRIES.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS GOOD.
PULLED PORK ON A BUN.
HE ONLY WANTS THE BEST.
SO CHECK OUT
THIS HEAVY HITTER...
THE TURKEY SANDWICH.
THAT'S BEEN ON THE MENU
SINCE DAY ONE.
IT'S AMAZING.
WHAT PTERODACTYL POULTRY
IS THAT?
WHOLE TOM TURKEY BREAST,
SKIN ON. COMES IN FROZEN.
IT'S THAWED OUT ENOUGH
THAT WE CAN APPLY THE RUB,
AND IT'LL STICK TO IT.
WHY AREN'T WE GONNA
THAW IT OUT ALL THE WAY?
SO I CAN PUT IT ON AT NIGHT
AND LET IT COOK ALL NIGHT
AND NOT HAVE TO GET UP
BEFORE 3:00 IN THE MORNING.
REALLY?
THERE'S SCIENCE TO IT.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA APPLY
THE RUB ALL OVER THIS,
JUST LIKE WE DID
THE BRISKET.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
NO BRINING?
NO BRINING.
POULTRY LOVES
TO BE BRINED.
THAT'S TRUE IF YOU HAVE
A PROBLEM KEEPING IT MOIST
THROUGH THE COOKING PROCESS.
OH.
OKAY. ON TO THE SMOKER.
RIGHT.
YOU SMOKE TURKEYS LIKE THIS?
MY FAVORITE.
TURKEY'S MY FAVORITE.
HOW LONG'S THIS GONNA GO ON?
10 TO 12 HOURS, 225.
SEMI-FROZEN.
MMM. TELL ME YOU DON'T
WANT TO JUST PICK
AT THAT CHUNK RIGHT THERE.
I'M CALLING THAT PIECE.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
I'M STARVING.
OKAY, WE'VE LET THE TURKEY REST
FOR 15 TO 20 MINUTES.
NOW PULL THE SKIN OFF.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU SEE THE PINK COLOR ON THERE?
PEOPLE GET SCARED,
THINKING IT'S UNDERCOOKED.
THAT THING'S BEEN COOKING
FOR 12 HOURS.
THAT PINK IS PERFECT. THAT'S
GONNA HAVE A NICE SMOKED FLAVOR.
THAT'S NOT DRY AT ALL.
LOOK AT THE BARK
ON THE OUTSIDE.
THAT'S NOT SKIN, FOLKS.
WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA ADD SOME
AU JUS TO THESE PIECES, TOO.
YOU CAN'T MAKE IT ANY BETTER,
CAN YA?
OH, YEAH.
I'M GONNA ADD A LITTLE RUB
TO THE AU JUS,
SQUEEZE ALL THE JUICE
WE CAN OUT OF THAT SKIN,
STIR THAT UP, LET IT RUN
RIGHT OVER IT AND SOAK RIGHT IN.
THAT'S A WHOLE NOTHER LAYER
OF FLAVOR.
WE NEED THAT.
MAN, THAT'S JUST PERFECT.
IT'S JUICY. IT'S FLAVORFUL.
IT DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER
THAN THAT.
I'VE SMOKED
A LOT OF TURKEYS.
I THINK THERE'S SOMETHING
GOING ON HERE
WITH YOU KEEPING THAT
ALL COMPACT,
GOING ON PARTIALLY FROZEN--
OUT OF BOUNDS.
TURKEY SPECIAL UP.
THE MEAT PRACTICALLY
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE RUB JUST HITS YOUR PALATE.
IT REALLY TASTES GOOD.
GOT THE BABY BACKS READY.
YOU CAN'T REPEAT THE FLAVOR
THAT THEY HAVE.
BURNT END PLATTER UP.
CAN'T GET ANY BETTER.
AND I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO KNOW
THE HISTORY BEHIND YOU GUYS,
'CAUSE I'VE SAT THERE
ENOUGH TIMES
AND WATCHED YOU GUYS WALK UP
ON STAGE. AMEN TO THAT.
YOU'VE DONE A GREAT JOB.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
NEXT UP ON THE TRIPLE "D"
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE TOUR,
THE QUESTION IS WHAT DO
FRENCH CUISINE AND KANSAS CITY
BARBECUE HAVE IN COMMON?
THIS DUDE.
FULL BABY BACK
COMING UP.
MORE WHEN WE COME BACK.
SO HERE WE ARE, TRIPLE "D"
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE TOUR
IN MISSION, KANSAS.
NOW CHECK OUT THIS STORY.
A LOCAL DUDE PACKS UP,
MOVES TO NEW YORK CITY
TO GET HIS CULINARY CREDS
IN A FRENCH RESTAURANT
AND SPENT 25 YEARS
IN THE HIGH-END JOINTS.
NOW IN THE MEANTIME,
HE'S MOONLIGHTING
IN COMPETITION BARBECUE
TILL HE REALIZES
THIS IS WHAT I LOVE.
IT'S TIME WE CHECK OUT
RJ'S BOB-BE-QUE.
HALF CHICKEN PLATTER.
THIS IS AWESOME.
WE LOVE THIS PLACE.
IT'S NOT JUST PLAIN BARBECUE.
HE PUTS A DIFFERENT SPIN
ON IT.
BRISKET SOUP.
SOUP?
BOB BURGER.
VERY TASTY.
(woman) IT'S A BOB THING.
A BOB THING?
EVERYTHING GOOD?
THAT'D BE BOB PALMGREN...
FULL BABY BACKS.
A HIGH-END CHEF WHO PICKED UP
BARBECUING AS A HOBBY,
THEN TRIED HIS HAND
AT A LITTLE COMPETITION.
YOU WERE COOKING FOR THE ROYAL
HERE IN KANSAS CITY
BEFORE IT WAS EVEN AT
THE AMERICAN ROYAL CENTER.
YEAH. UH-HUH.
WOW.
A COUPLE OF DECADES
AND DOZENS OF AWARDS LATER...
BEAUTIFUL.
HE TOOK HIS HOBBY FULL TIME.
BOB BRINGS THE CHEF
INTO THIS.
HE THINKS
OUTSIDE THE BOX.
JALAPEÑO SAUSAGES.
WONDERFUL.
COOKED IN A CORN HUSK.
FLAVORFUL,
CHUNKS OF PEPPER.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO NOW?
NOW WE NEED TO GRIND
SOME PORK UP
FOR THE SMOKED
JALAPEÑO SAUSAGES.
NICE BIG PORK BUTT,
BONE-IN.
YEP.
PORK BUTTS ARE PERFECT
FOR SAUSAGES.
PACKED WITH THEIR OWN FAT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE JUST CUTTING THIS
IN STRIPS
SO WE'LL BE ABLE TO FEED IT
NICE AND EASY.
THAT'S IT.
BUFFALO CHOPPER ON ONE SIDE,
GRINDER ON THE OTHER.
YEAH.
OH.
LOVE IT, DON'T YA?
SO THE IDEA HERE IS TO KEEP
THE EQUIPMENT COLD,
KEEP THE MEAT COLD, SO THAT FAT
DOESN'T GUM UP ON YOU.
GROUND PORK BUTT.
A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG,
FRESH GARLIC GOES IN THERE
CHOPPED UP, SALT.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
A BRATWURST SAUSAGE RECIPE.
CAYENNE PEPPER, GROUND PEPPER
AND THEN ALLSPICE,
SOME JALAPEÑOS DICED UP,
GOT A LITTLE SUGAR TO SWEETEN
LIFE UP A LITTLE BIT HERE,
DICED RED PEPPERS.
NICE COLOR.
LITTLE CHRISTMAS LOOK THERE,
YOU KNOW.
CHICKEN BASE.
AND THEN WE GET
TO HAVE THE FUN.
WE LIKE TO USE
OUR HANDS HERE.
THEN YOU GOT YOUR CORN HUSK.
SOAKED IN
A LITTLE WATER.
HOLDS MOISTURE IN
FOR A TAMALE,
BUT IT'LL LET SMOKE THROUGH
FOR SAUSAGE.
AND KEEPS
YOUR SAUSAGE MOIST, TOO.
WE TAKE ABOUT 6 OUNCES.
PUT THAT IN THERE
LIKE I GOT THERE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT UP.
TWIST EACH END HERE.
IF YOU'LL DO ME THE HONORS, I
JUST NEED YOU TO TIE ME A KNOT.
THERE YOU GO.
ONE MORE PIECE OF STRING.
NOW LONG IS THIS GONNA
GO DOWN IN THE SMOKER?
THIS IS GONNA TAKE
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
AND THE GOOD THING ABOUT THIS
IS YOU CAN LEAVE IT IN
FOR THREE HOURS--
UNBELIEVABLE--
AT A LOW TEMPERATURE,
AND IT'LL JUST KEEP ON
TAKING SMOKE ON.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PLATE 'EM UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE GOT JALAPEÑOS PLUS.
THIS SHOULD POP RIGHT OUT.
IT WORKS.
YEAH. GOT THE JALAPEÑOS
AND THE PEPPERS, GREAT STUFF.
SLICE IT UP HERE.
LOOK AT THE SMOKE RING.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE.
OH, YEAH.
MMM.
IT'S SUPER TENDER.
IT DID GET THE SMOKE. MMM.
IT WENT LONG ENOUGH
THAT THE JALAPEÑOS MELLOWED OUT.
I'M GONNA POLITELY TELL YOU
THAT I WILL BE
RIPPING OFF THE CORN HUSK
SAUSAGE IDEA.
OKAY. HEY.
LEGALLY BORROWED.
(woman) JALAPEÑO SAUSAGE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S A GREAT COMBINATION,
THE SAUSAGE AND THE JALAPEÑO.
IT'S TREMENDOUS. IT JUST
CRUMBLES IN YOUR MOUTH.
PORK SLAB.
ANYTHING YOU ORDER'S
GONNA REALLY BE GOOD.
ALL THE BASICS, THE BRISKET
AND THE PORK BUTT AND THE RIBS.
(woman) YEP.
AND HE HAS SOME THINGS THAT
OTHER PEOPLE JUST DON'T HAVE.
(Bob) DEEP-FRIED CORN'S UP.
MMM.
AND THE KERNELS ARE JUST POPPING
WITH ALL THAT BIG FLAVOR.
AND ONE OF HIS TOP SELLERS...
LAMB RIBS.
LAMB RIBS?
YEAH. YEAH
OH.
IT'S JUST EXCELLENT.
MY TASTE BUDS ARE DANCING.
VERY GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I SEE LAMB
RIBS ON MANY BARBECUE MENUS.
WELL,
THEY'RE A LITTLE DELICATE.
YOU GOT TO MAKE SURE
YOU DON'T OVERCOOK 'EM.
GET IT GOING, BOSS.
OKAY.
WOW.
THIS IS A HELLACIOUS RUB.
CORN DEXTROSE, IT'S A SWEETENER
MADE OUT CORN...
OKAY.
SALT, BASIL,
REGULAR CANE SUGAR.
GOT TO HAVE CHILI POWDER
IN A RUB.
A WHOLE MESS OF IT.
YOU GOT IT.
THIS IS OUR VEGETARIAN CHICKEN
BASE JUST FOR THE HECK OF IT.
AND THEN WE GOT
OUR GROUND CUMIN.
HE'S LIKE
A SPEED RUB BUILDER.
YEAH. SEASONING SALT,
BROWN SUGAR--
THIS IS REALLY COOL STUFF.
LAST TIME I SAW
SOMETHING LIKE THAT
WAS WHEN WE WERE
AT SMOKIN' GUNS.
OH, OKAY.
ROSEMARY, BLACK PEPPER,
GOT TO HAVE A LITTLE CAYENNE
PEPPER, AS THEY SAY DOWN SOUTH,
AND THEN WE GOT OREGANO,
MUSTARD FLOWER.
MUSTARD FLOWER,
NOT SEED.
FLOWER, YEAH, MUSTARD FLOWER.
IT'S GROUND.
OKAY.
ONION POWDER, ISRAELI PAPRIKA,
ALLSPICE.
THIS IS EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL.
THIS IS GINGER,
CORIANDER, GROUND, OF COURSE,
A BIT OF THYME ACTION,
GARLIC.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
FOR ONE RUB?
OH, YEAH.
WHO MADE THIS UP?
I DID.
TOOK 30 YEARS TO DO IT.
HOW MANY BATCHES OF THIS
ARE YOU MAKING A WEEK?
MAKE ONE A WEEK.
WE MAKE ABOUT 75 POUNDS
AT A TIME.
REALLY?
YEAH.
AND HAVE YOU COMPETED
WITH THIS RUB?
OH, YEAH. WE WON THIRD PLACE
AT THE AMERICAN ROYAL
WITH THIS RUB.
OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
YEAH. YEAH. WANT TO BE
PRETTY LIBERAL WITH IT.
YOU DEFINITELY WANT
TO RUB THE MEAT, THOUGH,
GET IT IN THERE.
NORMALLY, WE LET THESE SET FOR
AT LEAST THREE, FOUR HOURS
OR SOMETIMES OVERNIGHT, LET IT
KIND OF CURE A LITTLE BIT.
LEAVING A LITTLE BIT
OF THE FLAT MEAT IN HERE?
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
OH, NO, THAT'S SOME
OF MY FAVORITE.
OH, YEAH.
OKAY, SO THESE ARE GONNA
GO ON FOR HOW LONG?
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
WHAT TEMPERATURE?
250 DEGREES.
2 AND A HALF HOURS
AT 250.
RIGHT.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
OKAY.
THAT'S OUR LAMB RIBS.
THESE LOOK MORE LIKE
A SPARE RIB LAMB RIB.
RIGHT.
THEY CALL 'EM DENVER LAMB RIBS.
IT'S THE WAY THEY CUT 'EM.
BUT THEY ARE COMING
FROM DOWN HERE.
UH-HUH. YES, SIR.
JUST LIKE PEOPLE.
'CAUSE I'M PETITE
LIKE A LAMB.
JUST THINK OF ME
AS A BIG LAMB.
I'M MUTTON.
AND WE JUST CUT THROUGH 'EM.
PUT A LITTLE PRESSURE.
LOOK AT HOW IT JUST
FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
OH, YEAH. IT'S SWEET.
MMM. OH, MAN.
TENDER.
YEAH.
MMM. THE RUB
DOESN'T OVERPOWER IT.
IT SITS THERE
AND JUST KIND OF SUPPORTS IT.
YOU STILL GET
TO TASTE THE LAMB.
MM-HMM.
MMM. NICE SMOKE RING.
I THINK LEAVING
THAT SILVER SKIN ON,
WHICH I'M NOT A BIG FAN
OF ON BABY BACKS,
BUT ON THIS, I REALLY THINK
IT DID LOCK IN THE MOISTURE.
MMM. GREAT STUFF.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(woman) LAMB RIBS FOR YOU.
IT'S JUST SO GOOD. THIS IS LIKE
MY FOURTH OR FIFTH ONE NOW.
IS IT ALL OVER
MY CHIN?
NO. NO. NO.
AS FAR AS YOU KNOW...
BURNT ENDS SALAD'S UP.
EVERYTHING IS SO GREAT THAT I
DON'T NEED TO GO ANYPLACE ELSE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET
ANY BETTER BARBECUE THAN RJ'S.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
I LOVE IT.
I WORK WITH CORN HUSKS.
I MAKE TAMALES.
I'M FROM CALIFORNIA. RIGHT
THERE, I LEARNED ONE TODAY.
THANKS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HAD A GOOD TIME.
THANK YOU.
NEXT UP ON THE TRIPLE "D"
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE TOUR,
WE'RE GONNA HIT A JOINT THAT'S
ABOUT A HALF-MILE DOWN THE ROAD,
AND THIS IS WHERE
BARBECUE MEETS A DEEP FRYER...
TAKE THOSE OVER,
AND I'M GONNA DROP IT IN HERE.
NO.
YES.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WE'RE BACK ON THE KANSAS CITY
BARBECUE TOUR
AT A JOINT THAT
JUST SCREAMS TRADITION.
WE GOT AN OWNER WHO'S BEEN AT IT
SINCE HE WAS 14,
WE GOT A HANDMADE PIT
AND OVER THREE DECADES
OF HAPPY CUSTOMERS.
OH, YEAH, BY THE WAY,
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THE WAY
THEY DO BARBECUE CHICKEN.
THIS IS JOHNNY'S BBQ.
IT'S READY TO GO.
EVER HEARD OF ANYBODY SMOKING
CHICKEN AND DEEP-FRYING 'EM?
DROPPING CHICKENS.
NO.
TWO HALF A CHICKEN DINNERS
COMING UP.
A TRICK OWNER JOHNNY WHITE
PICKED UP...
DINNER TIME.
WORKING HIS FIRST BARBECUE GIG
44 YEARS AGO.
I LIKE THE WAY IT CAME OUT,
AND WE JUST STARTED SERVING IT
THAT WAY.
AND WHEN HE OPENED
THIS JOINT IN '78,
HE BROUGHT THE BIRD WITH HIM...
MMM.
SMOKING IT RIGHT OUT OF THE PIT
THAT JOHNNY BUILT...
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
WITH THE RUB THAT JOHNNY MADE.
YOU WON FOR MILD RUB FIRST PLACE
IN THE GREAT AMERICAN BARBECUE.
YES, WE DID.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE MAKING?
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
OH.
RED PAPRIKA RIGHT IN THERE,
SALT AND PLENTY OF IT,
BLACK PEPPER RIGHT HERE,
SUGAR, A LITTLE SWEETENER THERE,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
AND WE GOT SOME GRANULATED ONION
WE'RE GONNA THROW IN THERE,
GROUND CELERY.
NOT CELERY SALT,
GIVE IT A LITTLE MIX.
YEP.
OKAY, THIS IS SENSIBLE
MIXING EQUIPMENT.
RAW MIX READY TO ROLL.
TAKE THE SEASONING,
POP IT IN THE SHAKERS.
NOW WE CAN DO SOME CHICKEN?
YES, WE ARE.
3-POUND BIRDS SPLIT IN HALF.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS RUB ON.
WE'RE GONNA BEND
THIS WING BACK.
WATCH THIS. SEE WHAT
HE'S DOING RIGHT HERE,
FOLDS THAT WING BACK.
WHAT HAPPENS IS IT LOCKS
THAT WING TIGHTER TO IT
SO YOU DON'T LOSE
THE MOISTURE IN THE WING WHILE
YOU'RE WAITING FOR THE BREAST
AND THE THIGHS TO COOK.
LET ME GUESS.
YOU MADE THESE, TOO.
YEP. I'LL STICK THAT IN
RIGHT IN THERE.
PULL IT RIGHT UNDERNEATH...
(speaking indistinctly)
NO. THAT'S AWESOME.
THIS IS LIKE A SKI LIFT
FOR HALF CHICKENS.
OKAY, THIS IS
GONNA BE INTERESTING.
IT'S LIKE CAPONE'S VAULT.
PUSH IT UP.
HOLY...
HOW BIG IS THIS THING?
FULL, I CAN GET ABOUT 1,300 TO
1,500 POUNDS OF MEAT IN THERE.
YOU HAVE GOT TO--
HAY RAKE WHEELS.
KIND OF LOOKS LIKE
A WAGON WHEEL.
THIS IS LIKE THE MEAT
FERRIS WHEEL IN FLAVOR TOWN...
IT IS. IT IS.
'CAUSE I WANT TO--
DON'T TOUCH THAT BAR.
YOU WILL BURN YOURSELF.
HOLD IT LIKE THAT.
OVER THAT BAR.
YOU'RE DONE.
VERY NICE, HUH?
YOU SEE THAT?
YOU'RE GOOD. YEAH.
NEVER GET IT ABOUT 250.
HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA GO ON?
PROBABLY FOUR TO FIVE HOURS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
I'M GONNA SMELL GREAT.
WE JUST WANT TO SPREAD THOSE
APART SO THEY'RE NOT TOUCHING.
IF THEY TOUCH,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE RAW SPOTS.
THIS THING IS NUTS, MAN.
OKAY, SO ARE WE READY?
I'M READY.
I GOT TO GET THIS.
PLIERS.
WHAT ARE THE PLIERS FOR?
YOU WANT TO TAKE THAT HOOK OUT
WITH YOUR BARE HAND NOW?
OH, THAT DON'T BOTHER ME NONE.
OKAY.
THAT HOOK?
THERE'S A LITTLE TRICK
TO IT--THERE TO THERE.
WELL, I JUST GRAB IT
LIKE THAT.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
NOW HOW ARE YOU GONNA GET
THE HOOK OUT OF IT?
OH, YOU GET ALL FANCY
ABOUT IT NOW.
SO DO WE LET THESE REST
BEFORE WE BREAK INTO 'EM?
TAKE THOSE OVER,
AND WE'RE GONNA DROP IT IN HERE.
NO.
YES. WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME LOVE ON.
HOW LONG DOES IT STAY DOWN?
TWO TO THREE MINUTES.
NEVER SEEN THIS.
IT'S CRAZY.
ARE YOU READY?
I WANT YOU TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THAT,
SEE HOW GOLDEN
THAT GOT AROUND THERE?
SERVE IT UP, BOSS.
LOOK AT THAT SKIN.
TAKE THAT PERFECTLY GOOD
SMOKED CHICKEN...
AND FRY IT.
NO SAUCE ON THAT
UNLESS YOU WANT IT.
MMM.
SUPER TENDER, NICE SMOKE,
FLAVORFUL RUB,
BUT NOT OVERBEARING.
THE SKIN'S NICE AND CRISPY.
IT'S SUPER JUICY.
IT'S THE BEST OF BOTH WORLDS.
I'VE SEEN SOME FUNKY STUFF
IN MY DAY. THAT'S FUNKY.
WELL DONE,
CRAZY JOHNNY.
ALL RIGHT.
(woman) CHICKEN DINNER.
(man) IT'S AWESOME.
I ALWAYS GET THE CHICKEN.
ALWAYS GET
THE CHICKEN.
YEP, EVERY TIME.
THE SMOKINESS AND EVERYTHING
ABOUT IT IS JUST GREAT.
ORDER UP.
THIS IS PROBABLY SOME
OF THE BEST BARBECUE EVER.
AND SHE SHOULD KNOW.
TRACY SATTERFIELD FOUNDED
THE GREAT AMERICAN BARBECUE
FESTIVAL.
IT'S THE CONSISTENCY. YOU KNOW
THAT IT'S GONNA TASTE GOOD.
AND IT'S GONNA BE THE SAME WAY
YOU HAD IT LAST TIME.
HE'S GOOD AT IT.
(man) SLAB WORKING.
GET THAT OUT THERE.
YOU HAVE SUCH
A WIDE VARIETY.
FROM BRISKET...
NOT TOO SMOKY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
TO RIBS...
REALLY MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
TO THIS FAN FAVORITE...
PULLED PORK PLATE.
GOOD-LOOKIN' PORK BUTT.
WE DON'T CUT
THIS FAT OFF.
BECAUSE IT'S GONNA STAY
IN THERE FOR SO LONG,
I WANT TO LET THAT RENDER.
EVERYTHING GETS
THE SPECIAL JOHNNY RUB,
SAME RUB WE PUT ON
THE CHICKEN.
YES, SIR.
READY TO GO.
NICE LITTLE COLOR
OUT OF THAT PAPRIKA.
AND THEN ON THEY GO
TO THAT SMOKER AT 250
FOR ABOUT TEN HOURS.
WE CAN GET THIS STUFF
OUT OF HERE.
(whistles)
I'M GONNA FLIP THAT
RIGHT IN THERE LIKE THAT.
THAT'S GONNA BE LOVELY.
LOOK AT THE BARK
ON THAT.
OH, YEAH.
TENDER AS CAN BE.
PUT THIS PORK
IN THE TABLE RIGHT HERE.
I WANT TO MAKE YOU
A LITTLE PORK DINNER.
IS IT GONNA REALLY BE
A LITTLE PORK DINNER, JOHNNY...
NO, IT'S NOT.
OR IS IT GONNA BE--
THIS IS JOHNNY-SIZED.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
WE'LL PUT SOME PORK
RIGHT ON THAT PLATE.
PUT A LITTLE SAUCE
RIGHT THERE.
AND YOU MAKE
ALL THE SAUCES.
YES, SIR, WE DO.
THEN I'M GONNA SERVE YOU
A LITTLE BEANS AND SLAW.
HERE WE GO.
THIS FEELS LIKE TRUE KANSAS CITY
OLD-SCHOOL BARBECUE.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE.
MAKE YOUR OWN SLAW
AND DRESSING, ALSO?
YES, WE DO.
KIND OF MILD, JUST TO TAKE AWAY
FROM EVERYTHING.
THOSE BEANS RIGHT THERE ARE
SMOKED IN THE BARBECUE PIT
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS.
MMM. GREEN BELL PEPPER?
YES, SIR.
GET THE GREEN BELL PEPPER RIGHT
OFF THE BAT. NICE JOB, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
JOHNNY.
PULLED PORK,
IT'S VERY TENDER AND JUICY.
BABY BACKS
IN THE WINDOW.
IF YOU WANT GOOD BARBECUE,
THIS IS WHERE YOU GO.
(Johnny) READY TO GO OUT.
THIS IS DAMN GOOD.
THE PIT ALONE, YOU HAD ME
AT HELLO. VERY NICE PLACE.
THANKS.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
THANKS FOR COMING.
A LOT OF HAPPY PEOPLE.
YEAH, A LOT OF HAPPY PEOPLE.
NEXT UP ON THE TRIPLE "D"
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE TOUR,
WE'RE GOING TO THE SOURCE,
A PLACE
A LOT OF KANSAS CITY BARBECUE
JOINTS GET THEIR WOOD FROM.
ALL RIGHT.
ME? OH, I'M ROLLING
FOR THE RIBS...
THAT IS ONE OF THE MOST
RIGHTEOUS RUBS I'VE EVER HAD.
WHEN WE GET BACK.
NOW TO KIND OF ROUND OUT
THIS ADVENTURE,
WE'RE GONNA VISIT A PLACE THAT'S
SUPPLYING A LOT OF THE WOOD
TO THE BARBECUE JOINTS IN TOWN.
AND THESE FOLKS ARE NOT ONLY
JUST DOING BARBECUE WOOD,
THEY'RE DOING
BARBECUE THEMSELVES.
THIS IS WOODYARD BAR-B-QUE.
ALL RIGHT.
BUT IT REALLY LOOKS MORE LIKE
A PLACE THAT SELLS WOOD.
'CAUSE THAT'S BEEN
THE GOLDEN TICKET
AT THIS FAMILY BUSINESS
SINCE 1913...
THE SPECIALTY WOODS, THE PECAN,
OAK, THE CHERRY.
APPLE.
SMOKING WOOD.
RIGHT.
AND FIVE YEARS AGO, OWNER
FRANK SCHLOEGEL DECIDED...
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
IF THE WOOD'S GOOD ENOUGH
FOR EVERYBODY ELSE,
HE'D START COOKING ON IT, TOO,
AND ADDED BARBECUE
TO THE BUSINESS.
THE BARBECUE'S OUTSTANDING.
SMOKED CHICKEN,
I COULD EAT IT EVERY DAY.
(man) BEST BURNT END SANDWICH
I EVER HAD,
AND I DON'T CARE
IF I GET IT ON MY FACE OR NOT.
THE BABY BACK RIB.
HOW ARE THE RIBS?
FANTASTIC.
THE RUB IS EXCELLENT, UNLIKE
WHAT I'VE EVER TASTED BEFORE.
'CAUSE IT'S
A WOODYARD ORIGINAL...
IT MAY BE
A TRADE SECRET, ACTUALLY.
CRANKED OUT BY PIT MASTER
MARK O'BRYAN.
COMING ALONG NICELY.
SO WHAT'S THE RUNDOWN HERE
FOR THIS MAGICAL RUB?
IT'S QUITE UNIQUE.
WE START OFF WITH...
IS THAT TURMERIC?
TURMERIC.
I'M IN KANSAS CITY, RIGHT?
YES, YOU ARE.
SEA SALT.
A LITTLE SALT.
CARDAMOM.
CARDAMOM. SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
CLOVE, GRANULATED GARLIC,
CAYENNE PEPPER...
(whistles)
AND LAST, LEMON PEPPER.
THAT IS ONE OF THE MOST PECULIAR
RUBS I'VE EVER SEEN.
CARDAMOM, CLOVE AND TURMERIC
IN KANSAS CITY...
MM-HMM.
ON PORK RIBS?
NO SUGAR?
NO SUGAR.
ALL RIGHT.
SO MIX IT UP THOROUGHLY.
LOOK AT THOSE COLORS.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN
THE SPICE MARKET IN BAHRAIN.
LET'S GRAB THOSE RIBS.
ALL RIGHT.
SO LIBERALLY
JUST DUST THESE ON.
NOW AREN'T WE SUPPOSED TO TAKE
OFF THE SILVER SKIN FIRST?
NO, THAT STAYS.
SERIOUSLY?
IT HELPS RETAIN
THE MOISTURE.
THE SILVER SKIN?
THIS I GOT TO SEE.
PUT THESE PUPPIES ON.
WE'RE NOT COOKING PUPPIES,
JUST SO EVERYBODY KNOWS.
WE'RE GONNA THROW THESE
ON THE SMOKER.
SMOKING WITH PECAN WOOD?
YES.
HOW LONG.
THREE HOURS OR SO.
PUT HER DOWN, THREE HOURS,
THEN WE COME BACK.
NO BASTING, NO MOPPING,
NO NOTHING.
NO, SIR.
OKAY.
DONE.
WHOA! LOOK AT THE CRAZY COLOR
IN THIS.
WATCH THIS.
THAT IS TENDER.
YOU SEE THAT?
LOOK AT THAT SILVER SKIN.
THAT IS JUST COMING OFF
AS SHOE LEATHER,
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT, IT KEPT
A LOT OF MOISTURE INSIDE THERE.
IT DOES.
OKAY. MMM. WHOA.
THOSE RIBS ARE A KNOCKOUT.
TONS OF FLAVOR,
BETWEEN THE PECAN.
THAT IS THE MOST UNIQUE DRY RUB
I'VE TRIED.
I WOULDN'T EVEN
PUT SAUCE ON THIS.
NO.
AND TENDER. IT'S COOKED
ALL THE FAT OUT OF IT.
THAT IS ONE OF THE MOST
RIGHTEOUS RUBS I'VE EVER HAD.
NICE JOB.
I JUST ATE 20 POUNDS OF PORK.
(man) A SLAB OF BABY BACKS.
ENJOY, MAN.
THE RIBS HERE ARE GREAT.
LOVE THE RUB,
SPICY ENOUGH, NOT TOO HOT.
IT'S A GREAT COMBINATION.
I JUST LOVE THE FLAVOR, THE BEST
I'VE HAD IN KANSAS CITY.
I GOT AN ULTIMATE NUMBER ONE
AND A SMOKING KIELBASA.
(Guy) SO YOU KNOW GOOD
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE.
HOW DOES THIS PLACE DO?
EVERYTHING IS AWESOME.
IT'S KIND OF AN UNEXPECTED
TREASURE IN KANSAS CITY.
PEOPLE LIKE IT, AND WE'RE DOING
IT, SO WE STICK WITH IT.
IF IT AIN'T BROKE,
DON'T FIX IT.
YOU GOT IT.
FANTASTIC.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THE TRIPLE "D"
KANSAS CITY BARBECUE TOUR.
BUT DON'T WORRY,
I'M HEADED OUT ON THE ROAD
TO FIND EVEN MORE
OF AMERICA'S FAVORITE
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(train whistle blows)