HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
TAKE A WHIFF.
WHOA.
SAUCED...
DAVIESS COUNTY DIP.
GOOD STUFF.
AND SPICED...
LOOK AT THIS.
IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA...
BRISKET SANDWICH IN THE WINDOW.
THE CAFé NEAR THE WATER...
IT'S A WONDERFULLY
DIVERSE MENU.
WHERE BREAKFAST...
HERE'S THE FRENCH TOAST
FOR YA.
MEANS BEER...
BEER SYRUP.
MMM. OH, YEAH, NOW.
AND THE LOCAL CATCH
IS LOADED WITH FLAVOR...
MMM. IT'S FANTASTIC.
IN LEXINGTON, KENTUCKY...
(woman) MAC'S SLOPPY SANDWICH
GOAT.
THE BARBECUE JOINT...
THIS IS THE BEST.
SMOKIN' UP GOAT...
IT'S ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
MUTTON...
MMM.
AND MELON?
MELON SAUCE.
MELON SAUCE?
WHO NAMED IT MELON?
I DID.
AND OUTSIDE NASHVILLE...
CHICKEN KABOB SPICY.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
BEST FALAFEL
I'VE EVER HAD.
BRINGIN' A TASTE
OF BACK HOME...
THE LAMB KORMA
IS ALWAYS EXCELLENT.
TO THE MUSIC CITY CROWD...
THE OAKRIDGE BOYS.
WELCOME TO
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD, GUY.
HOW ABOUT RICKY SKAGGS?
(laughs)
AND, HEY...
LOOK AT THIS.
WHO NEEDS A PAN?
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME WE'VE
EVER COOKED WITH A SALT BLOCK.
THAT'S COOL.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA,
ABOUT NINE BLOCKS
OFF OF LAKE SUPERIOR
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT'S
A RESTAURANT COLLABORATION
BETWEEN, GET THIS, A COFFEE
SHOP/BOOKSTORE OWNER FROM DULUTH
AND A CHEF FROM TEXAS.
NOW WHAT THEY WANTED
WAS A FARM-TO-TABLE,
SUSTAINABLE FOOD RESTAURANT.
THE ONLY QUESTION IS WHAT
WERE THEY GONNA NAME IT,
SO THEY CAME UP
WITH THREE NAMES.
THIS IS TARAN'S MARKET PLACE
AT SARA'S TABLE
CHESTER CREEK CAFé.
BRISKET SANDWICH IN THE WINDOW.
HELLO, THIS IS AT SARA'S TABLE
CHESTER CREEK CAFé.
THE NAME OF THIS BUILDING
IS TARAN'S MARKET PLACE.
AND OWNERS CARLA BLUMBERG...
ORDER UP!
AND BARB NEUBERT...
HERE'S THE COFFEE.
EACH HAD THEIR OWN NAME
IN MIND.
WE COULDN'T AGREE
ON A NAME.
YEAH, WE COULDN'T AGREE
SO JUST ADD MORE NAME
TO IT.
LUCKILY THEY COULD AGREE
ON HOW TO DO THE COOKING.
POACHED
LAKE SUPERIOR WHITEFISH.
THEY USE AS MUCH LOCAL PRODUCE
AS POSSIBLE.
(woman) I GOT MY VEGGIES
FOR A HIPPIE.
ORGANIC, REALLY FRESH
AND GOOD. MMM.
HIPPIE FARM BREAKFAST.
MY FAVORITE THING
IS THE BREAKFAST.
THE PANCAKE,
REAL MAPLE SYRUP.
WHICH IS HARVESTED
IN NORTHERN MINNESOTA.
BUT THE BIGGEST HIT HERE...
HERE'S THE FRENCH TOAST
FOR YA.
CRANBERRY WILD RICE
FRENCH TOAST.
LOCALLY HARVESTED
WILD RICE.
IN A SCRATCH-MADE BREAD...
FRENCH TOAST GOING ON THE FLAT.
TURNED OUT BY
CHEF JILLIAN FORTE.
GONNA FLIP THE FRENCH TOAST.
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE SPONGE FOR
THE CRANBERRY WILD RICE BREAD.
THE SPONGE?
THE SPONGE.
FIRST WE'LL ADD
7 CUPS OF WATER...
ROOM TEMPERATURE WATER.
THEN THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
YEAST, AND SUGAR.
WE'RE GONNA TURN IT ON.
THE YEAST EATS THE SUGAR.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
FOR IT TO RISE?
ABOUT TWO HOURS.
ROCK IT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE SPONGE
AND PUT IT THE MIXING BOWL.
PUT SOME CANOLA OIL IN,
SALT.
AND SOME COOKED
WILD RICE.
YEP, GROWN IN MINNESOTA.
THE TEXTURE OF THE RICE IN
THE BREAD IS GONNA BE AWESOME.
WE'VE GOT ORGANIC EGGS.
CRANBERRIES.
SOME WHEAT FLOUR.
AND A LITTLE MORE A.P.,
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TURN IT ON.
SO ARE WE GONNA
PUNCH THIS DOWN AGAIN?
WE'LL LET THIS PROOF
ONE MORE TIME?
YEP, PROOF ONE MORE TIME.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
BREAK IT DOWN?
YEAH.
SO WE'RE GONNA FLOUR
THE WORK SURFACE,
TURN THE DOUGH OUT ONTO IT.
PUNCH IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
THEN I'M GONNA CUT IT
INTO FOUR LOAVES.
DO YOU THINK
THOSE ARE EQUAL WEIGHT?
NO.
NO, BUT IT'S CLOSE.
NO, BUT IT'S
A GOOD GUESSTIMATE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
PUNCH IT DOWN MORE.
FORM THE LOAVES.
LOAF-ATIZE THEM.
MM-HMM.
WANT ME TO SPRAY A TIN?
YEAH.
AQUA NET.
OKAY, THROW IT DOWN
ON ITS SEAM.
YEP.
NOW ARE THESE GONNA
PROOF UP AGAIN?
THEY WILL.
SO WE'RE GONNA FILL THE PAN,
PROOF UP AGAIN.
SPRAY THE LOAVES
WITH BUTTER.
AND THEN IT'LL BAKE
45 MINUTES AT 350?
MM-HMM.
WHAT'S OUR NEXT STEP?
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BEER SYRUP.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH BROWN SUGAR...
WHOA.
CORN SYRUP,
OATMEAL BEER.
LOCAL BEER?
IT IS,
LAKE SUPERIOR BREWING COMPANY.
DIG IT.
LET IT SIMMER FOR 15 MINUTES,
THEN I WHISK IN SOME CINNAMON.
THE CINNAMON-AMON-AMON-MINAMON.
MMM. OH, YEAH, NOW.
ALL THIS FOR FRENCH TOAST.
ALL THIS.
WE LIKE EVERYTHING
TO COME OUT PERFECT.
OKAY, SO NOW WE MAKE
THE FRENCH TOAST,
AND WE GET TO START EATING.
YES.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S COOLED DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
DO YOU MAKE ANYTHING ELSE
WITH IT?
NO, JUST FRENCH TOAST.
WOW. GET OUT OF HERE.
THIS TASTES GREAT AS IS. MMM.
THE RICE AND THE CRANBERRY
AND THE SWEETNESS, TANGINESS
THAT'S COMING OUT
OF THAT.
BUT WE'RE GONNA MAKE
FRENCH TOAST WITH THIS.
FRENCH TOAST.
THE BATTER IS EGG,
HALF-AND-HALF, CINNAMON,
POWDERED SUGAR, VANILLA,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG.
SEE THAT LITTLE DANCE MOVE?
GOOD TO GO?
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT.
AND THE BEER SYRUP.
AND THE SUPER SYRUP.
MM-HMM.
I DIG IT. LET'S ROLL.
ALL RIGHT.
THE WHEAT FLOUR, THE RICE,
THE CRANBERRY,
THE GREAT CRUST ON THE BREAD,
GIVES THAT REAL BACKBONE.
AND THE BEER SYRUP,
I CAN POUR THAT IN YOUR HAND.
REALLY NICE, DONE THE RIGHT WAY
WITH THE FRESHEST INGREDIENTS.
DYNAMITE.
FRENCH TOAST IN THE WINDOW.
WHILE THIS IS
A GREAT, SWEET FLAVOR,
IT TASTES LIKE
A GOOD, HEARTY MEAL.
LOVE IT.
THE BREAD
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
I CAN TELL IT'S HOMEMADE.
I CAN TELL IT'S FRESH.
TOFU CURRY SALAD.
IT'S A WONDERFULLY
DIVERSE MENU.
MEDITERRANEAN SANDWICH.
THEY HAVE A HUGE EMPHASIS ON
LOCAL, BUT THEY ALSO GO ETHNIC.
MISO SALMON UP.
SOMETIMES THEY EVEN THROW
LOCAL AND ETHNIC TOGETHER...
RED SEA SANDWICH
IN THE WINDOW.
WITH FISH CAUGHT
PRACTICALLY NEXT DOOR...
HERE'S YOUR FRESH
LAKE SUPERIOR WHITEFISH.
AND FLAVOR STRAIGHT OUT
OF THE MIDDLE EAST.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE HAWAJI SEASONING FOR
THE RED SEA FISH SANDWICH.
IT'S A YEMENITE THING.
IT'S FROM YEMEN?
YEAH, THE SPICE BLEND.
BLACK PEPPER...
TURMERIC.
TURMERIC, SALT,
CARAWAY, CARDAMOM,
A LITTLE BIT OF SAFFRON.
REALLY?
THIS IS GONNA HAVE
AWESOME COLOR.
SO I'M GONNA TAKE THE WHITEFISH,
SPRINKLE SEASONING ON THERE.
AND NOW WE'LL DREDGE IT
IN THE FLOUR.
OKAY, SO THIS
IS READY TO GO.
AND WHAT ELSE
GOES WITH THIS?
SLAW AND HARISSA.
SLAW AND HARISSA?
MM-HMM.
THERE'S GOT TO BE SOMETHING
SPECIAL IN THE SLAW.
THIS IS THE YEMENITE SLAW.
GIVE IT TO ME.
WE'RE GONNA MIX UP THE DRESSING
FOR THE SLAW FIRST.
SO WE'VE GOT WATER...
LEMON JUICE.
YOGURT, HONEY...
HONEY.
TAHINI.
CILANTRO.
IT'S GONNA HAVE
BIG FLAVOR.
SALT AND PEPPER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
WHISK IT UP.
A LOT OF PEPPER IN THERE.
YEAH.
OKAY, SO CAN I TASTE THIS?
WOW. THAT'S GONNA GO ON
THE SLAW FOR THE FISH?
MM-HMM.
OH, THAT'S GONNA BE KILLER.
GOT THE RED CABBAGE,
SOME SHREDDED CARROTS,
GREEN PEPPERS
AND SOME RED PEPPERS.
A RAINBOW.
IT IS.
NOW ADD THE DRESSING.
SO WE GOT THAT MIXED UP.
NEXT UP IS THE HARISSA.
OKAY.
REHYDRATED PEPPERS...
GUAJILLO PEPPERS.
THREE CLOVES OF GARLIC,
SALT, CORIANDER, CUMIN,
CARAWAY...
CARAWAY.
OLIVE OIL.
AND WE'RE GONNA TURN IT ON.
ALL RIGHT, NOW IT'S DONE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE TASTE.
MMM. NOW WE JUST GOT
TO COOK THE FISH.
JUST COOK IT.
SESAME OIL.
WE'RE GONNA PAN-FRY THIS
IN SESAME OIL?
WELL, IT'S
A SESAME/CANOLA OIL BLEND...
OKAY.
ANOTHER LAYER OF FLAVOR.
NICE SPLASH.
(laughs)
READY TO TURN?
YES, WE ARE.
SO YOU JUST PUT
A LITTLE FRY ON IT.
WE'VE GOT CIABATTA
TOASTING OVER HERE.
SO THIS IS THE HARISSA MADE
WITH THE GUAJILLO PEPPERS.
PUT THE FISH ON THERE,
TAKE SOME OF THE SLAW
THAT WE MADE,
AND VOILà.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE SLAW'S ON POINT.
THE BREAD'S PERFECT.
THE FISH IS NICE AND LIGHT.
YOU GET A LITTLE SPARKLE--
I DIDN'T USE THE WORD SPARKLE.
YOU GOT A LITTLE HIT
OF SOME GREEN BELL PEPPER.
SOMETIMES WE ADD
TZATZIKI TO IT.
WE SERVE IT ON THE SIDE,
HOMEMADE TZATZIKI.
MMM.
IT'S A FEEL-GOOD SANDWICH.
AFTER YOU EAT IT, YOU FEEL GOOD.
EXACTLY.
HERE'S YOUR
RED SEA FISH SANDWICH.
IT'S WONDERFUL. IT'S GOT
SO MANY LEVELS OF TASTE.
IT'S GREAT,
REALLY FLAVORFUL.
PORTUGUESE TENDERLOIN UP.
EVERYTHING'S GREAT HERE.
THANK YOU, LADIES.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
VERY NICE JOB, REALLY.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT,
YOUR TEAM IS REALLY REPRESENTING
YOU WELL ON THIS.
I KNOW. THEY'RE GREAT.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO KENTUCKY...
(woman) MAC'S SLOPPY SANDWICH
GOAT.
TO GET SAUCED.
MELON SAUCE.
GOES REALLY NICE
WITH THE TURKEY.
I'M HERE IN LEXINGTON,
WHICH IS CENTRAL KENTUCKY,
TO TRY A FAVORITE
FROM ACROSS THE STATE--
WESTERN KENTUCKY-STYLE BARBECUE
AT A JOINT THAT THE COUPLE NAMED
AFTER THEIR DOG.
THIS IS J.J. McBREWSTER'S.
(woman) SMOKED GOAT DINNER.
I'M HAVING THE GOAT,
WHICH IS AWESOME.
YOU JUST DON'T EXPECT TO SEE
GOAT ON A MENU.
HERE'S YOUR
MUTTON SANDWICH.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
I'M HAVING THE MUTTON.
IT'S EXCELLENT. IT HAS TONS
OF FLAVOR. IT'S ALL SMOKY.
THEY SMOKE THE MEAT
FOR A LONG TIME.
IT GIVES IT
A MORE RICH FLAVOR.
THIS IS AS WESTERN KENTUCKY 'QUE
AS IT GETS.
THANKS TO WESTERN KENTUCKY
NATIVE SUSAN MIRKHAN.
SLOPPY SANDWICH.
ALONG WITH HER HUSBAND NED...
I GOT ONE.
THEY'RE CRANKING OUT ALL
THE WESTERN KENTUCKY FAVORITES.
IT'S UNIQUE,
AND THEY'RE EXCITED TO FINALLY
HAVE WESTERN KENTUCKY.
'CAUSE THEY'VE BEEN LONGING
FOR IT.
THEY'VE BEEN LONGING
LONGING.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE THAT
I FOUND IN CENTRAL KENTUCKY
THAT HAS GOAT,
AND IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WHAT'S UP NOW?
GOAT.
THIS IS THE RUB--
KOSHER SALT, SEASONING SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
NOW WHOSE RECIPE'S THIS?
MINE.
AND THIS GOES ON EVERYTHING?
NO, THIS ONLY GOES ON
THE GOAT AND THE MUTTON.
LOOK AT THAT GOAT,
NICE BRIGHT RED,
WHITE FAT.
GOAT IS LEANER,
HAS LESS CALORIES AND LESS FAT
THAN CHICKEN OR TURKEY.
NO.
YEP.
SO WE GOT SHANKS.
WE GOT RIBS. WE GOT BUTTS.
WE GOT FLANKS, HINDQUARTERS.
WE GOT EVERYTHING.
YEP.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA SMOKE
THE GOAT AND THE MUTTON?
16 HOURS.
WOW.
WE'RE GONNA STACK 'EM
IN THE SMOKER.
OKAY, SO YOU'RE NOT GONNA GO
FLAT PIECES.
YOU'RE GONNA LET
EVERYBODY SHARE.
RIGHT.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD
ARE WE GONNA SMOKE WITH?
HICKORY.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S WESTERN KENTUCKY 'QUE.
WESTERN KENTUCKY.
AND WHAT TEMPERATURE
DO WE RUN THIS SMOKER AT?
225.
16 HOURS. (whistles)
WOW, THAT'S JUST REALLY
COOKS DOWN.
WE HAND-PULL EVERYTHING.
SO YOU GET SOME WITH BARK,
SOME ARE MORE MOIST.
BUT JUST LOOK AT THE COLOR
ON THIS. 16 HOURS.
MMM.
FULL OF BARK.
PEOPLE WHO HAVEN'T TRIED
GOAT BEFORE SHOULD TRY THAT.
HERE'S YOUR GOAT PLATE.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
I LIKE THE GOAT
OR THE MUTTON.
THE ORIGINAL BARBECUE FROM
WESTERN KENTUCKY WAS MUTTON.
GOOD BARK, GOOD SMOKE,
NOT OVERLY SEASONED.
(Susan) I GOT A MUTTON DINNER.
REAL NICE,
CLEAN FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU SEE EVERY DAY.
IT'S STANDARD
WESTERN KENTUCKY 'QUE.
SO IT NEEDS A STANDARD
WESTERN KENTUCKY SAUCE.
(Susan) THE DIP.
DAVIESS COUNTY DIP,
GOOD STUFF.
THIS IS THE PLATTER.
THAT IS THE GOAT.
AND THIS IS THE DIP.
THERE'S SEVERAL DIPS.
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY'S GOT
THEIR SAUCE RECIPE.
THIS IS THE ONE I PREFER.
THAT IS SUCH A RICH MEAT.
THIS MELLOWS IT OUT A LOT.
THAT REMINDS ME A LITTLE BIT
OF A CAROLINA-STYLE.
AND THAT'S JUST ONE OF
THEIR FIVE HOMEMADE SAUCES.
THE WESTERN SAUCE--
DELICIOUS.
THE WESTERN SAUCE
IS MY FAMILY'S RECIPE.
I'VE BEEN MAKING IT
SINCE I'VE BEEN YEA HIGH.
AND IF YOU ARE FROM
WESTERN KENTUCKY,
AND YOU'VE HAD PULLED PORK,
YOU'VE HAD THIS SAUCE.
(man) I LIKE THE MAC'S
MEAN SAUCE,
GIVES A LITTLE BIT
OF A KICK TO IT.
THE RAZZ B QUE SAUCE--
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
(Susan) MELON SAUCE.
THAT'S WHAT BARBECUE SAUCE
SHOULD TASTE LIKE.
MELON SAUCE?
WHO NAMED IT MELON?
I DID.
EVEN THOUGH
THERE'S NO MELON IN IT.
HOW DID YOU GET MELON?
I LIKE THE NAME OF THAT.
JUST...
YEAH.
VINEGAR.
HOW MANY GALLONS?
OH, 1 AND SOME.
THANK YOU.
I'M HELP MAKIN' THE MELON.
SOME WATER,
ONIONS, CHOPPED CELERY,
BLACK PEPPER...
(whistles)
SALT...
SALT.
AND BAY LEAVES.
OH! THAT IS A MESS
OF BAY LEAVES.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIMMER?
AT LEAST 45 MINUTES.
THE LONGER IT SIMMERS
THE BETTER THE STOCK.
STOCK? WE'RE MAKING A STOCK?
YEP.
STRAIN IT, AND THEN WHAT
ARE WE GONNA DO WITH IT?
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
A ROUX.
MARGARINE.
YOU'RE GONNA SHAKE IT
THROUGH THIS?
YOU'RE GONNA SIFT YOUR FLOUR
INTO YOUR...
YES, GOT TO SIFT THE FLOUR.
MAKE IT MELT IN THERE
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
NOW WHY DON'T YOU
START STIRRING?
WELL, YOU'RE IN MY WAY.
WHAT COLOR WE GOING FOR?
A LIGHT TOASTY.
SO WE'RE GOING FOR
AN ALMOND?
YEAH.
ROUX'S READY.
KETCHUP.
DO YOU WANT A RUBBER SPATULA?
GOT ANY RUBBER SPATULAS?
OH, YOU USE YOUR HAND.
OH, YOU DIDN'T DOUBLE UP
THE GLOVES.
THAT GIVES ME GOOSE BUMPS.
(laughs)
SUGAR, PAPRIKA,
WORCESTERSHIRE.
WORCESTERSHIRE-SH-SHIRE.
SHA-SHA-SHA.
A WHOLE MESS OF HOT SAUCE.
AND OUR STOCK.
WE STRAIN?
YEP.
AND?
MOLASSES.
OKAY, BROWN SUGAR.
YEP.
(laughs)
YEAH. (laughs)
IT'S GONNA SIMMER ABOUT
TWO AND A HALF OR THREE HOURS.
VERY LAST 20 MINUTES I'M GONNA
ADD SOME MINCED ONION TO IT.
SO WE LET THIS SIMMER, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT ON WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT ON
SOME TURKEY.
SMOKED TURKEY?
YEP.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT.
DRY RUB FOR THE TURKEY--
SEASONING SALT, REGULAR SALT,
BLACK PEPPER,
SECRET INGREDIENT.
NUTMEG IN THAT?
NUTMEG, NICE WITH POULTRY.
INTO HERE?
YEP. THANK YOU.
THERE WE GO. OH. OH.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
OOH.
THOUGHT IT WAS PERFECT.
BIG GIGANTIC TURKEY BREAST.
BONELESS.
SO WE'RE GONNA INJECT.
BUTTER AND TURKEY BROTH
BEING INJECTED INTO THIS BIG,
OLD TURKEY BREAST.
THEN WE'RE GONNA SPRINKLE
ALL THIS GOODNESS ON THERE.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO HERE.
NOW WE DO THE SPRINKLE FEST?
AND IT WOULDN'T BE A RUB
IF YOU DIDN'T RUB.
I'M GONNA WRAP IT IN FOIL,
BECAUSE WE'RE GONNA SMOKE IT.
IN WHAT? FOIL.
FOI-AL.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE THE TOP
OF THE FOIL OPEN A LITTLE.
OH, YOU'RE--
YOU'RE TENTING IT.
YOU'RE NOT NECESSARILY
WRAPPING IT.
RIGHT.
OH.
HOW MANY HOURS?
16.
225.
READY.
OKAY, TURKEY TIME.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE.
WOW, THE SHEEN.
NOW THIS COMES AS A PLATTER,
COMES AS A SANDWICH,
COMES AS A THIS,
COMES AS A THAT.
YEP.
WOW. LOOK AT THAT.
THIS THE FAMOUS MELON SAUCE.
YEP, DARK, RICH,
SWEET, MAHOGANY.
OH. MAHOGANY IS A GREAT WAY
TO SAY THAT.
GOES REALLY NICE
WITH THE TURKEY.
IT DOES HAVE
THAT DEEP, RICH,
RON BURGUNDY,
LEATHER-BOUND BOOKS.
YES.
THIS IS MAC'S SLOPPY SANDWICH.
OKAY, WELL, THE TURKEY TO BREAD
RATIO HAS GONE ABOUT 300 TO 1.
OH, THIS IS
A SLOPPY SANDWICH.
HOW...
HOW ARE YOU GONNA EAT THAT?
WELL, "GUY'S BIG BITE,"
YOU KNOW.
MOVE OVER, TURKEY.
NO, NOT YOU, THAT TURKEY.
MMM.
THE TURKEY'S SUPER TENDER,
REALLY GOOD FLAVOR.
THE RICH MAHOGANY
GOES SO WELL.
SEE, THAT'S WHAT
IT SHOULD BE CALLED.
MELON SAUCE.
(laughs)
IT SHOULD BE CALLED
RICH MAHOGANY
LIKE RON BURGUNDY SAYS IT.
SLOPPY TURKEY
WITH A SIDE OF MASHED POTATOES.
IT IS SO JUICY AND TENDER.
I LOVE THAT MELON SAUCE.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S RICH MAHOGANY.
YES.
(Susan) MAC'S SLOPPY SANDWICH
GOAT.
I'M A FAN
OF WESTERN KENTUCKY BARBECUE.
THIS IS THE BEST.
(Susan) OH, YOU'RE KILLING ME.
(Guy) THIS IS THE NEW SAUCE THEY
HAVE HERE AT J.J. McBREWSTER'S.
IT'S CALLED RICH MAHOGANY.
(laughs)
NEXT STOP,
WE'RE HEADING TO NASHVILLE...
THE CHEF IS JUST AMAZING.
FOR STEAK...
I'M, LIKE,
IN STICK MANAGEMENT HERE.
ON A SALT BLOCK.
THAT'S COOL.
SO HERE I AM ABOUT
10 MILES NORTH OF NASHVILLE
TO VISIT A JOINT THAT'S, WELL,
NOT YOUR TYPICAL
NASHVILLE RESTAURANT.
BUT THEN AGAIN,
IT'S NOT YOUR TYPICAL
MEDITERRANEAN PLACE EITHER,
NOR IS IT THE TYPICAL
INDIAN RESTAURANT.
I GUESS YOU KIND OF HAVE
TO PUT IT TOGETHER
AND SAY IT'S A NASHVILLE
MEDITERRANEAN INDIAN EXPERIENCE.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
THIS IS CAFé RAKKA.
FALAFEL APPETIZER READY.
BEST FALAFEL
I'VE EVER HAD. MMM.
THE CHICKEN TIKKA MASALA--
MY FAVORITE.
WE HAVE A WEDNESDAY NIGHT
DATE NIGHT,
AND THIS IS OUR
WEDNESDAY NIGHT THING.
A LOT OF REGULARS.
AND THIS BEING MUSIC CITY,
EVEN COUNTRY MUSIC SUPERSTARS.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE OAKRIDGE BOYS.
WELCOME TO
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD, GUY.
HOW DOES THIS STACK UP?
THIS IS JUST
INCREDIBLE EATING.
WE KIND OF LIKE
THAT INTERNATIONAL FLAVOR.
SO DOES THIS
14-TIME GRAMMY WINNER.
HOW ABOUT RICKY SKAGGS?
(laughs)
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
SON, THIS IS FINE STUFF
RIGHT HERE.
CHICKEN KABOB SPICY.
I WATCHED MY GRANDMOTHER COOK
MOST OF THIS STUFF.
BACK IN SYRIA...
THIS IS DONE.
WHERE RIYAD AL-KASEM...
LAMB CHOPS READY.
EVERYONE CALLS HIM
CHEF RAKKA, GREW UP.
I LOVE TO COOK.
AND HIS RECIPES
GO BACK CENTURIES,
LIKE THIS TOP SELLER.
THE LAMB KORMA
IS ALWAYS EXCELLENT.
IT'S A COMPLEX FLAVOR.
SO LEG OF LAMB.
WE'RE GONNA CLEAN IT.
TAKE ALL THE FAT OFF.
YEAH, I'LL LEAVE A LITTLE BIT,
GIVES IT...
MOISTURE.
THE GREAT FLAVOR, TOO.
CUT THE MEAT.
THIS IS GONNA BE COOKED.
IN?
IN SPICES ONLY.
PEANUT OIL.
(Guy) GREEN CARDAMOM.
THIS IS WHAT WE CALL
THE LEAF OF CARDAMOM.
THIS IS A PLANT,
VERY GOOD.
WE ADD IT TO IT.
NOW THIS ONE
IS BLACK SYRIAN CARDAMOM.
SO THIS IS DRIED CARDAMOM?
YEAH.
WE'RE GOING ALL IN
WITH THIS.
BAY LEAVES, TWO STICKS
OF CINNAMON, CUMIN...
CUMIN.
CORIANDER AS WELL GOES IN.
TURMERIC.
SAFFRON, SALT...
HIMALAYAN SALT.
PEPPER.
THESE SEASONINGS ARE JUST
REALLY OPENING UP RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE GONNA ADD GARLIC,
GINGER.
LITTLE GARLIC.
WE HAVE TO STIR 'EM.
TAKE A WHIFF.
WHOA.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR LAMB IN.
COATING THIS WHOLE THING?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THROW A LID.
THIS IS GONNA TAKE
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE A SAUCE
THAT GOES ALONG WITH THAT,
AGAIN, TOASTING UP
ALL THE SPICES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
PEANUT OIL, FENNEL SEED,
AJOWAN...
AJOWAN. ADD TWO.
CINNAMON STICKS,
CORIANDER, CUMIN...
TURMERIC,
BLACK SYRIAN CARDAMOM.
SAFFRON...
WOW, THIS IS LIKE
A SPICE FEST.
GINGER, PURéED GARLIC AGAIN...
(whistles)
OUR CARDAMOM LEAVES.
HIMALAYAN SALT,
GREEN CARDAMOM,
LITTLE BAY LEAF.
THAT'S IT. WE STIR.
WHEN THE SPICES ARE BROWN...
THIS LOOKS GOOD.
I'LL BE OVER HERE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
TOMATO PURéE TO IT.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
APPROXIMATELY AN HOUR
AND YOU CANNOT TAKE
YOUR EYE OFF IT.
YOU BURN IT.
YOU'RE DONE.
(whistles)
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOUR CREAM,
THE HOMEMADE YOGURT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE MILK.
WE'RE GONNA STIR VERY GOOD.
IT'S ALL MIXED UP.
COOK ON VERY LOW.
THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
STIR OCCASIONALLY,
EVERY THREE, FOUR MINUTES.
THE SAUCE IS DONE.
THE LAMB IS FINISHED.
NOW...
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE LAMB KORMA.
ADD ONE LADLE OF SPICE WATER.
WITH THE CUMIN AND THE LEMON
AND THE SALT AND THE GARLIC.
GONNA TAKE THE KORMA SAUCE,
BRING IT TO A BOIL,
SOME OF THE LAMB,
ONE DRY FIG.
COVER.
AND LET IT SIMMER
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
IT TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
THERE, THAT'S IT.
WE'LL COME RIGHT HERE
TO PLATE.
DRIED CHERRY AND...
RAISINS.
WHEN YOU ADD THE CILANTRO,
YOU ADD IT AT THE BOTTOM.
YOU SUBMERGE IT WITH THIS,
AND AS YOU EAT, IT COMES UP
AND HITS THE NOTES.
I DON'T KNOW TO CALL HIM CHEF
OR MAESTRO.
PARSLEY.
AND THAT'S HOW IT GOES.
MMM. ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
FANTASTIC.
YOU ARE SURROUNDED IN FLAVOR.
WOW. YOU'VE PROBABLY NOT HAD
LAMB THIS TENDER. MMM.
THIS IS LIKE
MEDITERRANEAN BOLOGNESE.
I'M SORRY. I GOT TO DO IT,
ONE MORE BITE.
MMM. OUTSTANDING.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR LAMB KORMA.
MULTILAYERED TASTE.
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
ALL OF HIS FOODS
ARE GOOD.
BIRYANI EXTRA SPICY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IS THE KEY
ELEMENT OF WHY IT'S SO GOOD?
OH, I THINK THE SPICES.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S LIKE I'M IN A SPICE MARKET
IN ITSELF.
I JUST GROUND THIS ONE
THIS MORNING.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE
AND FRESH.
HE GOES TO THE MARKET,
GETS FRESH STUFF,
FRESH OLIVE OIL
FROM SYRIA.
SOMETIMES WHEN YOU COME IN
HE'LL SAY, "I JUST MADE
SOME FRESH CHEESE."
(woman) IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
MMM.
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
WE GOT MILK. WE'RE MAKING
THE FARMER'S CHEESE.
WE HEATED THE MILK
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
WHAT KIND OF HEAT
ARE WE ON?
WE GOT IT FULL BLAST.
I'M GONNA ADD...
VEGETABLE RENIN, IT'LL SEPARATE
THE WHEY AND THE CURD?
UH-HUH.
STIR FOR 10 TO 15 MINUTES.
WANT ME TO STAND IN?
YOU GO AHEAD.
THE MILK STARTS
TO LOOK LIKE WATER.
IT'S STARTING TO GET
REAL THIN.
THIS IS WHERE YOU REALLY NEED
TO BE GENTLE WITH IT.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO BREAK IT UP,
'CAUSE YOU WANT IT
TO HAVE TEXTURE.
YEAH. YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS READY.
AND NOW YOU'RE JUST GONNA
SCOOP IT UP? THIS IS AWESOME.
LET IT SIT IN
THE CHEESECLOTH.
HIMALAYAN SALT.
YOU REALLY NEED THE SALT
TO GET INTO THE CHEESE.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
THE BLACK SEEDS.
NIGELLA SEED.
MIX IT A LAST TIME.
WE'RE GONNA SQUEEZE IT GOOD,
GET ALL THE WATER OUT.
BRING IT TO A PLATE,
OPEN IT ONE MORE TIME,
SOME ON THE TOP.
THIS IS READY.
IF IT TASTES HALF AS GOOD AS
THIS WHOLE PROCESS WAS...
THIS HAS BEEN IN THE FRIDGE
FOR MORE THAN 24 HOURS.
IT HAS TO BE DONE RIGHT.
FRESH HERBS,
THE FRESH MINT WITH THE TOMATO.
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
MMM. KIND OF A CROSS BETWEEN
A FETA, A RICOTTA.
YOU'RE INCREDIBLE.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
WHAT A COOL DUDE.
HERE'S YOUR CHEESE PLATE.
HIS FRESH CHEESE--
FABULOUS.
IT HAS AN EXCELLENT, SOFT,
ALMOST A GOAT CHEESE FLAVOR.
THE CHEF IS JUST AMAZING.
(man) THE WAY
HE PREPARES IT...
MOUSSAKA'S READY.
IS DIFFERENT THAN
YOU'LL GET ANYWHERE ELSE.
YEP, LIKE THIS ONE.
FILET MIGNON KABOBS.
COOKED ON, GET THIS,
A HIMALAYAN SALT BLOCK.
WOW. LOOK AT THIS.
THAT'S COOL.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
LAMB BIRYANI EXTRA SPICY.
AT CAFé RAKKA IN
HENDERSONVILLE, TENNESSEE...
HERE YOU GO.
OWNER RIYAL AL-KASEM
A.K.A. CHEF RAKKA...
SAFFRON KABOB.
IS SERVING UP WHAT HE CALLS
EAST MEDITERRANEAN FAVORITES...
KABOB HALABI.
TO A WHOLE RANGE OF FANS...
MMM.
INCLUDING COUNTRY MUSIC LEGENDS
THE OAKRIDGE BOYS.
THIS IS NUTS.
THERE'S NOWHERE ELSE LIKE THIS
AROUND HERE.
AND NOTHING ELSE AROUND HERE
LIKE THIS ONE.
FILET MIGNON.
FILET MIGNON KABOBS.
COOKED ON
A HIMALAYAN SALT BLOCK.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THAT WORKS OUT,
BUT IT WORKS OUT FOR ME.
COOKING WITH A SALT BLOCK--
IS IT TRADITIONAL?
VERY TRADITIONAL.
THE MEAT WILL SUCK
JUST ENOUGH SALT,
AND WHEN YOU TASTE IT TODAY,
YOU'LL SEE.
YOU'RE GONNA CARVE
FILET MIGNON.
ALL THE SKIN'S TAKEN OFF THIS,
ALL THE FAT.
YEAH.
CUT THE FILET MIGNON
INTO MEDALLIONS.
SO YOU KNOW THAT IF YOU COOK
A LITTLE BIT ON THIS SIDE,
A LITTLE BIT ON THAT SIDE,
YOU'RE GONNA COME OUT
MEDIUM RARE.
MEAT'S DONE. NOW WHAT?
NOW WE'RE GONNA PREPARE
THE MARINADE--
BLACK PEPPER, THE GARLIC,
NOW HERE'S CHOPPED PARSLEY,
LEMON JUICE...
OKAY.
OLIVE OIL,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
THE ONLY THING I DON'T NOTICE
IS THE SALT,
BUT WE'RE COOKING
ON SALT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
PUT OUR MEAT IN IT.
AND BECAUSE THIS IS FILET
AND IT'S VERY TENDER...
YEAH.
THE MARINADE GOES
VERY QUICK.
NOT MORE THAN TEN MINUTES.
THEN WE SKEWER IT.
PUT IT HERE,
GET IT READY TO COOK IT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE DRESSING.
THIS IS SIMILAR TO THE MARINADE
THAT WE JUST MADE.
SIMILAR TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA START AGAIN
WITH BLACK PEPPER,
GARLIC SMASHED,
ITALIAN PARSLEY...
LITTLE SALT ADDED TO IT.
LEMON JUICE.
YOU WANT ME TO GRAB
A LITTLE OIL?
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME OIL.
IS THAT GOOD?
YEAH.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA WHISK IT,
AND WE SET IT ASIDE NOW.
EXCELLENT.
PUT THE SALT BLOCK
ON THE GRILL.
SO WHAT TEMPERATURE DO YOU
THINK WE HAVE THIS HERE?
WHOA. THAT'S SMOKIN'.
NOW I'LL GIVE THE VEGETABLES
AT LEAST A MINUTE HEAD START.
FLIP THESE?
WOW, THAT'S HOT.
YEAH.
SOME PEOPLE WHO ARE SMART
USE TONGS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE FILET MIGNON SKEWERS ON.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S COOL.
I'M, LIKE,
IN STICK MANAGEMENT HERE.
(speaking indistinctly)
ONE TO TWO MINUTES
ON EACH SIDE.
SO IT DOESN'T PUT
A LOT OF COLOR ON IT.
IT WON'T LOOK LIKE
IF IT'S GRILLED.
I LOVE IT.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S DONE.
THAT'S IT.
HERE IS OUR... DRESS,
SAME THING FOR THE VEGETABLES.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THIS
RIGHT NOW. CRAZY.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
ITALIAN PARSLEY
AND WE'LL COVER IT
WITH TANDOORI BREAD.
TO KEEP IT WARM.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MMM. BOY, TALK ABOUT
GREAT FLAVOR.
MMM. FILET MIGNON,
MEDIUM RARE.
I GET A LITTLE BIT OF THE SALT,
BUT IT'S NOT SALTY.
NO.
THAT'S GREAT. MMM.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
ON TRIPLE "D"
THAT WE'VE EVER COOKED
WITH A SALT BLOCK.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD JOB. THANK YOU, MAN.
DELICIOUS.
HERE YOU GO.
HERE'S THE FILET MIGNON.
IT HAS A VERY GOOD FLAVOR.
TENDER STEAK
BUT SEASONED WELL, REALLY GOOD.
CAFé RAKKA'S GOT
SOME INCREDIBLE FOOD.
MOUSSAKA EXTRA SPICY.
(man) EVERYTHING'S
SO FRESH-TASTING.
I MEAN, YOU CAN EAT
YOURSELF SILLY,
AND YOU LEAVE FEELING GOOD.
HERE YOU GO.
AND IT'S ALWAYS
A TOTALLY UNIQUE EXPERIENCE.
AWESOME.
GREAT.
CHEF, THANK YOU.
WHAT A PLEASURE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA LOVE
THIS PLACE.
WOW, ANOTHER GREAT
TRIPLE "D" ROAD TRIP.
HEY, YOU CAN GET ALL
THESE GREAT ROAD TRIP RECIPES
IF YOU GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'VE NEVER MET
A BAD BEEF SANDWICH.
(laughs)
SHE LAUGHS AT HER OWN JOKES
LIKE I DO.