HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THEY WANT HOMEMADE
PAPPARDELLE?
WE SHEET IT,
AND THEN WE CUT IT.
MADE TO ORDER.
RIGHT TO ORDER.
IN ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA...
ORDER UP!
THE LOCAL PUB...
I DON'T GO ANYPLACE
ELSE TO HAVE BURGERS.
WHERE "MADE TO ORDER"...
READY TO FLIP!
MEANS A BURGER FILLED
WITH SHORT RIBS...
DELICIOUS.
AND EATING LOCAL...
"AUSTIN, MINNESOTA, 55912."
MEANS SPAM.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
IT'S LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN A JALAPEñO POPPER
AND SOME KIND OF NUGGET.
IN EAST BOSTON...
MMM, SO GOOD.
THIS SECOND GENERATION
ITALIAN JOINT...
SHRIMP SCAMPI UP.
LOADING THE RAVIOLI...
YOU DON'T SKIMP
ON THE FILLING.
WITH LOBSTER.
MMM. OH, DUDE,
I'M BEYOND IMPRESSED.
AND IN LINDEN, NEW JERSEY...
BUFFALO CHICKEN'S READY.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE
WHAT THEY'RE UP TO...
I'VE EXPANDED INTO A FULL-BLOWN
CATERING COMPANY NOW.
AT THE VERY FIRST
TRIPLE "D" DINER...
ENJOY.
WE EVER ROLLED INTO.
WHERE YOU GONNA
GET A BURGER LIKE THIS?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
NOW WHEN TRIPLE "D"
ROLLS INTO BALTIMORE,
WHAT ARE WE EXPECTING TO FIND?
YOU KNOW IT--BLUE CRAB.
MIAMI? MOFONGO.
SO HERE WE ARE IN
MINNEAPOLIS/ST. PAUL AREA,
AND WHAT DO WE EXPECT TO FIND?
STUFFED BURGERS,
ALSO KNOWN
AS THE JUICY LUCY.
NOW LAST TIME WE WERE HERE,
WE WERE AT THE NOOK
GETTING THE JUICY NOOKIE,
BUT TODAY WE'RE IN THE MERRIAM
PARK NEIGHBORHOOD OF ST. PAUL,
WHERE THEY'RE
NOT MAKING THE LUCY,
AND THEY'RE
NOT MAKING THE NOOKIE,
THEY'RE MAKING THE BLUCY.
THIS IS THE BLUE DOOR PUB.
BLUCY, FRIES.
BLUCY IS A STUFFED BURGER
WITH GARLIC AND BLUE CHEESE.
TO DIE FOR.
AND THEN THE BLUCY.
ENJOY.
THE FLAVORS BLEND
IN A WAY THAT'S DIFFERENT
IF YOU PUT 'EM ON TOP.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THE BLUCY?
STUFF-A-LICIOUS,
I THINK.
STUFF-A-LICIOUS?
STUFF-A-LICIOUS, YEAH.
STUFFED BURGERS--
PRETTY COMMON
IN THIS AREA?
OH, YEAH.
JUST NOT THE WAY RESTAURANT
VETS JEREMY WOERNER...
SOME AU JUS.
AND PAT McDONOUGH...
ORDER UP!
ARE DOING 'EM.
YOU KNOW, YOU START
THINKING UP COMBINATIONS.
WE JUST TOOK IT
AND RAN WITH IT.
LUAU, FRENCHY
AND A MERRIAM.
UNUSUALLY,
A RED CURRANT JELLY.
IT'S A GREAT
COMBINATION OF FLAVORS.
BANGKOK!
STUFFED WITH
COCONUT-SOAKED MOZZARELLA,
AND THEN THIS IS THE BEST PART--
THE CURRY DIPPING SAUCE.
ASIAN FRENCH DIP?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHTY, THE BLUCY.
FLAGSHIP BURGER IS A BLUE CHEESE
AND GARLIC STUFFED BURGER.
YOUR FLAGSHIP BURGER.
FLAGSHIP.
I'D LIKE TO FLOAT ON THAT
BURGER TO FLAVOR TOWN.
SO WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS
WITH THE MEAT?
YES,
AND THEN THAT BURGER MIX IS WHAT
WE USE FOR ALL OF OUR BLUCYS.
WE HAD TO COME UP
WITH SOME KIND OF A MIX
THAT WAS GONNA ALLOW OUR BURGERS
TO ADHERE TO ONE ANOTHER,
'CAUSE THAT'S PART
OF THE PROCESS OF MAKING
A JUICY LUCY, AND KEEP
ALL THE CHEESE INSIDE.
PUT THE WHITE BREAD IN THE BOWL,
THEN WE ADD THE BUTTERMILK.
WE JUST WANT TO GET THIS
DOWN TO A PASTE.
YOU WANT ME TO GET YOU
A SMALLER FORK?
I HAVE A COCKTAIL FORK
IN THE CAR
I CAN GET OUT HERE FOR YOU.
ADD OUR GARLIC HERE,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
WHOA!
STEAK SAUCE.
ANY PARTICULAR KIND?
JUST STEAK SAUCE.
REALLY?
YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW
THAT I BUY THAT.
NOPE.
NOW WE'LL WHISK IT
TOGETHER.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD.
GROUND BEEF IS 80/20?
IT'S 80/20, FREE RANGE,
NO ADDITIVES, NO HORMONES.
JUST POURS IN, MIXY-MIX.
RIGHT.
THIS IS THE NEW IMPROVED
"KARATE KID" TRAINING CAMP.
I'M GUY FIERI
THE SENSEI HERE.
I'M JUST GONNA BALL UP
A COUPLE PATTIES HERE.
PATTY PAPER DOWN.
THROW THAT ON.
YOU HAVEN'T
STUFFED 'EM YET.
NO, I'M GONNA
SMASH 'EM, THOUGH.
OKAY.
PARCHMENT GOES AWAY.
IS THAT REALLY
HOW IT'S DONE HERE?
YEAH, EVERY DAY IT SOUNDS
LIKE A MACHINE GUN.
RUBBER BUCKET
ON THE TABLE.
YEP, A LITTLE--
A LITTLE MORE NATURAL.
THIS IS LIKE
A WRESTLING--HEY!
HA! SEE, DROP THE HAMMER.
THE GARLIC,
BLUE CHEESE.
BIG OL' NUGGET OF IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA SEAL IT
AND FORM IT.
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE MAKING
A MEAT PUPUSA.
HERE WE GO.
HOW DO WE KNOW
WITHOUT DIGGING--OH.
YOU GUYS HAVE A WHOLE
COMBO SYSTEM HERE?
WE DO, YEAH,
A WHOLE PICKING SYSTEM.
THERE'S A WHOLE
PICKING ORDER?
YEP.
EVERYTHING'S ON THE FLATTOP?
ANYBODY EVER COME AND MESS
WITH THE OTHER COOK
AND START CHANGING
TOOTHPICKS?
THAT WOULD BE,
UH, NOT GOOD.
WE LIKE TO DOME IT,
'CAUSE THIS IS 1/2-POUND PLUS
WITH THE CHEESE IN THERE.
IT TAKES QUITE A WHILE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE STEAM.
DOMO ARIGATO.
ALL RIGHT.
HOW MANY DOMES
DO YOU HAVE?
WELL, WE HAVE LITTLE DOME,
AND WE HAVE BIG DOME.
ALMOST READY?
WE'RE GETTING THERE, YEP. NOW
WE'RE GONNA BUTTER OUR BUNS.
WHERE DO THE BUNS
COME FROM?
A LOCAL BAKERY.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
WE SERVING THESE AT?
WE LIKE TO SERVE
'EM AT MEDIUM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WE READY?
READY.
PUT A FEW PICKLES
ON HERE.
JUST PICKLES?
JUST PICKLES, THAT'S IT.
BURGER HERE, THROW IT DOWN.
NO LETTUCE, NO TOMATO,
NO MUSTARD...
NO MUSTARD.
NO KETCHUP, NO MAYO.
ALL THE LOVE
ON THE INSIDE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WAY TO CRAM IT ALL IN THERE.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT
WE DO.
NO LEAKAGE ON THE GRIDDLE.
I'M IMPRESSED.
THANK YOU.
WOW. THE MOUNT VESUVIUS
OF CHEESE
THAT COMES GUSHING
OUT OF THIS THING.
THE MEAT'S GOT A REALLY GREAT
TEXTURE TO IT.
I PICK UP THE WORCESTERSHIRE
THAT'S IN THE STEAK SAUCE.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE PICKLE
COUNTERACTS WITH THE SALTINESS
AND THE TANG
OF THE BLUE CHEESE.
YEP, YEP.
I CAN SEE WHY THE BLUCY
IS SO POPULAR.
I MEAN, THAT'S ABOUT
EIGHT BITES--
I'M A QUARTER OF THE WAY
THROUGH IT...
YEP.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
LOOK AT ALL THAT CHEESE.
SURE HAS A TON OF FLAVOR.
YEP.
BLUCY AND FRIES.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I LOVE BLUE CHEESE.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT COMBO.
GREAT STARTER BURGER.
YEAH, IT'S THE BASIC...
READY TO FLIP!
THEN THEY REALLY START
BUILDING 'EM.
THE GATSBY
WITH FRENCH FRIES.
THAT'S ME.
GRUYERE CHEESE, SHORT RIBS
AND THEN A RED WINE REDUCTION.
DELICIOUS.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
WOW, SCREAMS FOR A GLASS
OF RED WINE.
ABSOLUTELY.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
TIMES I SAY A BURGER
NEEDS A GLASS OF WINE.
HOW ABOUT A GLASS OF O.J.?
BREAKFAST, COMIN' IN.
CHEDDAR, BACON
AND AN EGG ON TOP.
IT'S LIKE A GREASY SPOON
BREAKFAST
MEETS THE MOST DELICIOUS
BURGER YOU'VE EVER HAD.
THEY'RE SO CREATIVE.
JIFFY BURGER AND TOTS.
AND THEN IT'S LIKE,
WHY STOP THERE?
LET'S KEEP GOING.
WHAT CAN WE DO?
THINGS THAT YOU FIND
IN YOUR KITCHEN,
AND THEN THEY SOMEHOW
PUT TOGETHER
AND JUST MAKE IT AMAZING.
DROPPING GREEN BEANS.
AND THEY'RE DOING IT
WITH EVERYTHING.
A BREADED DEEP-FRIED
GREEN BEAN--VERY, VERY TASTY.
DEEP-FRIED PICKLES
WITH THE AIOLI SAUCE.
DEEP-FRIED PICKLES.
THAT EQUALS GOOD.
AND THEN THERE'S
THEIR OWN TAKE
ON EATING LOCAL.
SPAM BITES DOWN.
"AUSTIN, MINNESOTA, 55912,"
WRITE IN, SAY HI, SEND A RECIPE.
LOOK, THERE'S A PICKLE IN IT,
AND SPAM AND CHEESE.
AND IT'S BREADED AND DEEP-FRIED,
AND IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
WE CALL THESE
OUR SPAM BITES.
IT'S PROBABLY THE ONLY GOOD
DECISION I'VE EVER HAD
AT 3:15
IN THE MORNING...
REALLY?
WAS DOING SOMETHING WITH SPAM,
CREAM CHEESE, PICKLE,
UH...
WHAT, WERE YOU PREGNANT?
GONNA DICE THIS UP WITH--
WELL, HEY, IT'S MINNESOTA,
WE GOTTA BRING THIS OUT.
THERE WE ARE.
WE SCOOP THAT UP.
PICKLE.
OKAY.
WE JUST DICE THAT UP FINELY,
ADD IT WITH THE SPAM HERE.
ONE OF THESE HUGE BOWLS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND WHAT DO WE GOT HERE
IN THIS MIX?
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF SALTINE
CRACKERS AND POTATO CHIPS.
JUST LEAVE IT LIKE THIS,
THIS AND SOME OF THAT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MOVE ON
TO OUR CREAM CHEESE.
GET IT ON MY HANDS
A LITTLE BIT,
MAKES THE CREAM CHEESE
A LITTLE MORE MANAGEABLE.
ROLL 'EM UP.
YOU GOTTA TRY THE PICKLE FLAVOR
ON THE SPAM. IT'S AWESOME.
LITTLE SPHERES OF THAT.
GOT A FEW ROLLED OUT.
HEARKEN BACK TO POTTERY CLASS,
I MAKE A LITTLE BOWL,
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GOODNESS HERE.
YOU'VE GOTTA
BE KIDDING ME.
LOAD IT UP.
YOU GOT A...
CHEESE--THERE IT IS,
SO WE TAKE THESE,
AND, UH, NOW LET'S GO
MAKE THE BATTER.
START OFF WITH A LITTLE
FLOUR HERE, BLACK PEPPER.
(whistles)
A LITTLE CAJUN SEASONING,
ADD...
BUTTERMILK.
BUTTERMILK HERE,
ABSOLUTELY.
I LIKE HOW YOU GET YOUR STUFF
RIGHT UP TO THE RIM THERE, SON.
AND THEN WE ADD
SOME EGG HERE,
AND THEN I'M JUST GONNA WHISK
THIS TOGETHER RIGHT HERE.
IF ANYBODY AT HOME OR AT MYERS
RESTAURANT SUPPLY IS WATCHING,
UH, PLEASE SEND
BIGGER BOWLS.
NOW INTO THE BATTER.
INTO THE BATTER.
HOW MANY COME
WITH AN ORDER?
UH, YOU GET SIX
IN AN ORDER.
COVER THIS UP WITH OUR CRUMBS,
PULL 'EM OUT.
ALL OF THAT
FOR ONE ORDER?
ALL THAT FOR ONE ORDER.
SO THEN WE JUST TAKE THIS
OVER TO THE DEEP FRYER.
LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
FIVE, FOUR, THREE,
TWO--PULL 'EM.
(whistles) LOOK AT
HOW DENSE THEY LOOK.
NOW WE ACTUALLY
HAVE A, UH--
OH, PLEASE, DO TELL.
SWEET CHILI LIME SAUCE
THAT WE SERVE WITH 'EM.
'CAUSE THAT SOUNDS
LIKE SPAM.
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S MY KIND OF EASTER EGG.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO TELL YOU.
IT IS SO DENSE
AND CRUNCHY
THAT YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO GET
LIKE A LITTLE PICK HAMMER
TO GET THROUGH IT.
YOU'VE GOT SALTY, BRINY,
SWEET, TANGY,
ALL GOING ON
INSIDE OF IT,
AND THE SRIRACHA
CHILI SAUCE...
GOES NICE WITH IT.
IT'S LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN A JALAPEñO POPPER
AND SOME KIND OF NUGGET.
GREAT USE OF SPAM.
A TON OF CREAM CHEESE.
ALL RIGHT.
NICE.
THANK YOU.
SPAM BITES ARE DONE.
CREAM CHEESE AND THE PICKLES--
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU WON'T LEAVE
UNSATISFIED.
GOT THE CURRY
FOR THE BANGKOK.
I DON'T GO ANYPLACE
ELSE TO HAVE BURGERS.
I HAD TO STOP BY
ON THE FIRST DAY...
MM-HMM.
BEEN HERE EVER SINCE.
IT'S GREAT TO DISCOVER THESE
LITTLE GEMS ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
ONE OF THEM.
NICE JOB.
THANKS, GUY,
APPRECIATE IT.
AWESOME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
AWESOME.
UP NEXT...
I NEED THE PAPPARDELLE
PLEASE!
WE'RE HEADING
TO EAST BOSTON...
THIS IS AUTHENTIC
ITALIAN HERE.
TO BREAK OUT THE BIG GUNS.
THIS IS ACTUALLY
GOING TO BE QUITE COMICAL--
HIS BIG HANDS
AND THIS.
I'M HERE ON THE EAST SIDE
OF BOSTON
AT THE CORNER OF PUTNAM
AND SARATOGA,
IN WHAT WAS A PREDOMINANTLY
ITALIAN NEIGHBORHOOD.
NOW YOU WATCH TRIPLE "D,"
YOU KNOW I LOVE ITALIAN FOOD.
IT'S GOTTA BE HAND MADE.
IT'S GOTTA BE HOMEMADE.
IT'S GOTTA BE THE REAL DEAL.
AND FROM WHAT THE LOCALS TELL
ME, RINO'S PLACE IS ALL THAT.
(speaking indistinctly)
BEST FOOD IN BOSTON.
TENDERLOIN.
CAME HERE FOR LUNCH, AND I
BROUGHT MY WIFE BACK FOR DINNER.
THE GNOCCHI
IS SO DELICIOUS.
CHICKEN PARM.
THAT'S THE WAY YOU SAY IT
THE RIGHT WAY, BY THE WAY--
IT'S CHICKEN "POM."
THE FRUTTI di MARE--
THIS IS AUTHENTIC
ITALIAN HERE.
AND SO IS SECOND-GENERATION
OWNER TONY DiCENSO.
SHRIMP SCAMPI UP.
WERE YOU BORN IN ITALY?
BORN IN ITALY, MIGRATED HERE
WITH MY FAMILY IN '85.
MY PARENTS BOUGHT THE BUSINESS,
WERE READY TO RETIRE IN '94,
AND I'VE HAD IT
EVER SINCE.
THIS IS WHAT
YOU WERE BORN TO DO.
YES, I LOVE TO COOK.
HOMEMADE ORECCHIETTE.
THEY WANT HOMEMADE PAPPARDELLE?
WE SHEET IT AND THEN WE CUT IT.
RIGHT TO ORDER.
RIGHT TO ORDER, THEN RIGHT
IN THE BOILING WATER.
I NEED THE PAPPARDELLE,
PLEASE.
THE HOMEMADE PASTAS--
EVERY ONE IS GOOD.
EVERYTHING
IS SCRATCH MADE.
YES, EVERYTHING
I HAVE A LOBSTER RAVIOLI.
THE RAVIOLI IS MADE FRESH.
JUST VERY DELICIOUS. MMM.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE WE
MAKING FIRST, BOSS?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
BOIL OFF SOME LOBSTERS...
OKAY.
FOR OUR LOBSTER RAVIOLIS.
WE HAVE TWO LOBSTERS--
ABOUT A POUND
AND A HALF EACH.
IS THE WATER SEASONED?
YEAH, A LITTLE SALT.
DROP 'EM IN THERE...
FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES?
10, 15 MINUTES.
OKAY, WHEN THESE GET DONE,
WE'LL GET STARTED.
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA
SHOCK THEM IN AN ICE BATH.
SO WE STOP
THE COOKING PROCESS.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
ALL THE MEAT OUT OF THE TAIL
AND THE CLAWS.
THIS IS FOR THE FILLING.
YES.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GET
ALL THE LOBSTER MEAT OUT.
AND THE LEGS ALSO.
WE'RE GONNA
ROLL OUT THE LEGS.
YES.
THIS IS ACTUALLY GOING
TO BE QUITE COMICAL--
HIS BIG HANDS AND THIS.
GET AFTER IT, BOSS.
SQUEEZE IT,
ALL THE MEAT RIGHT OUT OF IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
LIKE LOBSTER SAUSAGE.
THAT MEAT IS SUPER SWEET
AND SUPER TASTY.
LOTTA WORK FOR
A LITTLE LOBSTER.
SO THIS GETS US
THE BOWL OF LOBSTER.
NOW WE CHOP IT UP,
PUT A LITTLE SAUTé ON IT.
SOME EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SOME SHALLOTS.
WHERE DO YOU GET
YOUR OLIVE OIL FROM?
ITALY.
OF COURSE. WE GOT
THE CHOPPED UP LOBSTER MEAT.
THERE WE GO. HEY,
A LITTLE FRESH PARSLEY.
ITALIAN PARSLEY?
YES. SALT, PEPPER.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
YEP. PULL IT
OFF THE HEAT.
LET IT COOL DOWN.
ABOUT A HALF AN HOUR.
SOMEBODY'S GOTTA TRY IT.
CAN'T WE JUST
EAT IT LIKE THAT?
I KNOW,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
OKAY, YOU READY?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR FILLING.
GO.
FRESH RICOTTA.
WHERE YOU GETTING
THE RICOTTA FROM?
FROM ITALY ALSO.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE, LIKE A TRAM
THAT GOES BACK AND FORTH?
NOTHING BUT THE BEST.
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
WHEW.
SOME PARSLEY, SALT, PEPPER,
THAT CHILLED LOBSTER MEAT.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER.
JUST FOLD IT.
I LIKE TO LEAVE IT CHUNKY.
YES.
NO, I WANT
SOME TEXTURE.
NONE OF THIS
PURéE STUFF.
NO, I WANT CHUNK
OF LOBSTER.
THERE YOU GO,
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO WE GOT THIS READY.
NEXT THING IS MAKING THE PASTA.
EXACTLY, YES.
PLEASE, WILL WE EAT SOON?
YES, WE WILL, YES.
KILLIN' ME.
THE FLOUR,
MAKE THE WELL.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR EGGS.
WE MAKE PASTA AT HOME
QUITE A BIT,
MY BOYS AND I.
THIS IS HOW MY GRANDMOTHER
TAUGHT ME,
MY MOTHER.
THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
ADD THE EGGS, THEN SALT,
A LITTLE EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
BECAUSE OUR PITCHFORK
IS IN THE SHOP,
WE'RE GONNA WHIP
THE EGGS WITH THIS.
EACH TIME HE MIXES IT AROUND,
A LITTLE BIT MORE FLOUR
CATCHES IN, INCORPORATING
INTO THE EGGS.
NOW IT'S KIND OF
LIKE PASTY,
WE CAN START FOLDING
IN THE FLOUR.
AND NOW JUST AS MUCH FLOUR
WILL STICK TO IT AS IT CAN.
AND DO YOU DO
ALL THE PREP AND EVERYTHING
IN THIS LITTLE KITCHEN?
YES.
AND YOU'RE HERE
SIX DAYS A WEEK?
YES, SIR.
I DO ALL THE SHOPPING
AND EVERYTHING,
I PICK EVERYTHING OUT MYSELF,
MY PRODUCE, EVERYTHING.
WAIT A MINUTE--
SERIOUSLY?
YES, SIR, I GO TWO, THREE
TIMES A DAY TO THE MARKET.
GROWING UP IN ITALY, WE GREW
OUR OWN VEGETABLES, HERBS,
AND EVERYTHING, AND WE RAISED
ALL OUR OWN ANIMALS.
I RAISED MY OWN
ANIMALS, TOO.
YEAH.
I NAMED THEM
HUNTER AND RYDER.
OKAY, HERE'S THE DOUGH.
PUT A BOWL OVER IT.
WE'LL LET IT REST FOR ABOUT
A HALF AN HOUR, 45 MINUTES.
SET IT ON THE COUNTER,
NEXT THING, YOU'LL JUST
START ROLLING THIS OUT.
AND THIS IS A HAND CRANK
PASTA MACHINE--
NO ELECTRIC PASTA MACHINE
FOR THIS GUY.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
OKAY, RIP IT
WITH YOUR HAND, FLOUR,
WE'RE MAKING A SHEETED PASTA.
WE WANT TO GENTLY DO THIS,
SO YOU START THIS
ON THE LARGEST NUMBER...
EXACTLY,
AND WE'RE GONNA WORK OUR WAY
DOWN TO LIKE 2 1/2.
WOW, LOOK AT THIS.
SWEET MUSIC TO THIS RIGHT NOW--
THIS SHOULD BE A VIDEO.
WHEN I GET
TOWARDS THE END,
WE'RE GONNA FOLD IT AND MAKE IT
A LITTLE BIT MORE WIDER,
BETTER CONSISTENCY.
SO IT REALLY FITS INSIDE
OF THE RAVIOLI MOLD.
EXACTLY, THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE FLOUR.
RIGHT ON TOP OF THE MOLD.
JUST PRESS IT IN A LITTLE BIT,
'CAUSE THAT'S WHERE
THE FILLING'S GONNA GO IN.
WOW, YOU DON'T SKIMP
ON THE FILLING.
NOPE.
I JUST WANT YOU TO SEE THIS--
THAT RIGHT THERE IS PLENTY,
BUT THAT IS HOW MUCH
HE PUTS IN A RAVIOLI HERE.
CRAZY.
NOW WE DO ANOTHER SHEET?
YEP, RIGHT ON TOP.
PRESS DOWN TILL THE TWO
PASTAS SEAL TOGETHER.
FLIP IT OVER.
ONE, TWO...
TAKE THE MOLD OFF, AND THEN
CUT IT WITH THE DOUGH CUTTER.
SMOOTH THE RIDGES OUT,
THEN WHAT WE DO
IS PRESS 'EM
ON ALL SIDES.
MAKE SURE THAT THEY SEAL,
THERE'S NO AIR IN THESE.
NOW YOU HIT A LITTLE FLOUR,
PUT 'EM ON A SHEET TRAY.
WHAT WE'LL DO
IS WE'LL FREEZE 'EM.
THEY'LL SEAL EVEN BETTER,
AND THEN YOU'RE OFF TO GO.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE LOBSTER
RAVIOLI SAUCE NOW.
FANTASTIC.
SOME EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SHALLOTS, LOBSTER MEAT.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH, SALT, PEPPER,
LET THAT SWEAT A LITTLE BIT.
NEXT WE'LL ADD OUR BRANDY.
WHOA!
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED?
YEAH, THAT'S WHY--THAT'S WHY--
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
ONCE IT'S DONE FLAMING,
TOMATO SAUCE,
HEAVY CREAM, BUTTER,
SOME FRESH BASIL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA LET IT
REDUCE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
ON TO THE 15-STEP RAVIOLI.
PUT ON EIGHT RAVIOLIS
TO AN ORDER,
FOR ABOUT TWO
AND A HALF MINUTES.
YOU WANT TO HAVE THIS
ON A SIMMER BOIL,
NOT A RAPID BOIL, SO YOU
DON'T BEAT THESE THINGS UP.
EXACTLY.
RAVIS ARE FLOATING.
YES, LET 'EM DRAIN,
ADD IN THE SAUCE.
NOW A LITTLE GRATED CHEESE--
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
HERE COMES
THE MONSTER MEAL.
JUST DROP 'EM RIGHT IN THERE.
LOBSTER RAVIOLI.
I CAN FEEL THE FIRMNESS
IN THE PASTA.
MMM, AHH.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I DON'T KNOW IF I SHOULD HUG YOU
OR KIDNAP YOU TO CALIFORNIA.
YOU GOT TONS OF LOBSTER MEAT,
A LITTLE BIT OF BRANDY
IN THAT SAUCE
WITH THOSE TOMATOES--MMM.
THERE IS NOTHING
I WOULD CHANGE ON THAT.
I'VE BEEN TO ITALY.
I'VE HAD GREAT PASTA,
AND I GOTTA TELL YOU, YOU'RE
FOLLOWING ALL THE PRINCIPLES
BUT ONE.
WHAT'S THAT?
RIDICULOUS PORTION.
OH, PORTION.
LET ME SHOW YOU--
NORMAL--
NORMAL, YES.
TONY, I'M NOT KIDDING.
EASILY, 2 POUNDS OF FOOD.
DUDE, I'M BEYOND
IMPRESSED.
THANK YOU.
LOBSTER RAVIOLI.
WONDERFUL
LOBSTER SAUCE.
BIG CHUNKS
OF LOBSTER MEAT.
LOBSTER RAVIOLI.
ONE THROUGH TEN.
IT'S A TEN.
NO QUESTION.
ALL HIS FOOD HERE
IS A TEN.
STUFFED EGGPLANT.
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME.
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
I WANTED THE FRESHEST POSSIBLE,
LIKE MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO DO.
MY GRANDPARENTS IN ITALY--
ALWAYS LOVED WATCHING THEM
IN THE KITCHEN MAKING THE SAUCE,
MAKING THE PASTA.
AND FOR TONY...
SPAGHETTI.
THERE'S NEVER BEEN
ANY OTHER WAY.
PLATING THE FRUTTI di MARE.
FRESH FOOD, FRESH PASTA.
ORDER UP!
(bell dings)
EVERYTHING IS HOMEMADE HERE.
SAUSAGE RAPI.
YOU CAN ALWAYS
FIND SOMETHING.
CHICKEN CAROZELLA.
SOMETHING THAT
YOU'LL LOVE.
BUT IF YOU CAN'T DECIDE...
IF YOU DON'T KNOW IF YOU WANT
VEAL OR CHICKEN OR SHRIMP...
WE GOT A RINO'S SPECIAL.
YOU JUST GET THIS.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
YEAH, THERE WE GO.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
OH, MY GOSH!
RINO'S PLACE...
CHICKEN PARM.
A NEIGHBORHOOD INSTITUTION
FOR ALMOST 25 YEARS.
OKAY, GUYS,
LOBSTER RAVIOLI.
IT'S ON THIS LITTLE CORNER
IN BOSTON,
AND WHAT'S GOING ON INSIDE
MIGHT BLOW YOUR MIND.
PUT THE STUFFED EGGPLANT
IN THE OVEN!
BECAUSE OF TONY. IT HAS
EVERYTHING TO DO WITH TONY.
PUT UP THE DISHES, COME ON.
THE GUY HAS PASSION.
HE HAS SOUL.
NEXT WE GOT COMING OUT--
LIMONCELLO.
EVERYTHING THAT TONY MAKES
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
'CAUSE FOR ITALIAN-BORN CHEF
TONY DiCENSO...
PORCINIS.
THIS IS ALL PERSONAL.
HOMEMADE LINGUINE.
I NEED TO HAVE HANDS ON
AT ALL TIMES.
PLATE UP A GNOCCHI!
I PICK OUT ALL MY PRODUCE,
MY MEATS, MY FISH.
AND HOW OFTEN
DO YOU DO THIS?
EVERY DAY. SOMETIMES TWO,
THREE TIMES A DAY.
NO.
YEAH. THAT'S HOW I MAKE
MY, UH, SPECIALS.
LIKE ROASTED
PORK TENDERLOIN...
JUST A REALLY UNIQUE DISH.
WITH A CHERRY BALSAMIC
HONEY SAUCE...
BROTHER, THAT'S A MONSTER.
MMM.
SHRIMP SAUTéED
IN A LEMON LIQUEUR...
SHRIMP LIMONCELLO UP!
AND HIS ULTIMATE...
RINO'S SPECIAL.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW IF YOU WANT
VEAL OR CHICKEN OR SHRIMP,
YOU JUST GET THIS.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
PLATING UP
A RINO'S SPECIAL.
WITH MUSHROOMS, CREAMY MARSALA
SAUCE. IT'S A REALLY GOOD DISH.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE
ONTO NOW, BOSS?
GONNA MAKE
SOME VEAL STOCK.
FOR THE...
RINO'S SPECIAL THAT
WE'RE GONNA BE DOING.
SO VEAL BONES ARE DOWN.
YES, WE'LL POP THESE
IN THE OVEN--500-DEGREE OVEN.
ROAST 'EM OFF.
ABOUT 45 MINUTES, PULL 'EM OUT,
RUB TOMATO PASTE ON 'EM...
OKAY.
PLACE 'EM BACK IN THE OVEN
FOR ANOTHER 15, 20 MINUTES.
MIREPOIX.
CELERY, ONIONS,
SKIN ON AND EVERYTHING,
CARROTS--IN THE OVEN,
ROAST ABOUT 15, 20 MINUTES.
PULL 'EM OUT.
SO THE ROASTED VEG.
HERE'S OUR VEAL BONES.
WOW, GREAT COLOR.
INTO THE STOCKPOT--
COLD WATER.
ALL THAT GREAT ROASTED FLAVOR
WITH THE MIREPOIX--
THIS IS GONNA COME UP TO A BOIL
AND THEN SIMMER
FOR ABOUT FOUR
OR FIVE HOURS.
THEN STRAIN IT
INTO THE RINO'S SPECIAL.
GOT IT. TAKE A LOOK AT THIS--
THIS ALL IS GOING INTO ONE DISH.
YES.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
OKAY, EXTRA VIRGIN
OLIVE OIL.
TAKE OUR VEAL,
DREDGE IT IN SOME FLOUR.
JUST A.P. FLOUR, RIGHT?
THAT'S IT. ADD OUR VEAL. NOW
WE TAKE OUR CHICKEN TENDERLOINS,
DREDGE 'EM IN THE FLOUR,
SHAKE OFF THE EXCESS FLOUR,
BROWN 'EM REAL QUICK
ON ONE SIDE...
LOOK AT 'EM.
THEN WE'LL ADD
OUR MUSHROOMS...
OYSTER.
CHOPPED PORCINIS, SHIITAKES.
WHICH I CAN SMELL
RIGHT NOW--WOW.
AND WE'RE GONNA
LET THAT SAUTé.
YOU GET YOUR MEAT
FROM A BUTCHER?
PICK IT OUT MYSELF.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
AND THE MUSHROOMS?
PICK 'EM OUT MYSELF.
PICK 'EM OUT YOURSELF,
OF COURSE YOU DO.
SALT AND PEPPER.
YOU MINED THE SALT IN EGYPT
YOURSELF. OF COURSE YOU DID.
SOME BRANDY,
DEGLAZE THE PAN.
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
THERE WE GO.
TELL ME THAT DOESN'T
NEED A MARSHMALLOW.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
VEAL STOCK.
THAT'S THE VEAL STOCK
WE MADE.
YES, SIR. HEAVY CREAM,
THEN TWO SHRIMP.
SHRIMP ARE GONNA
GO IN LAST.
BUTTER, LET IT SIMMER,
THE SAUCE REDUCES NICE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THAT WITH?
HOMEMADE PASTA.
DO WE HAVE ANY PASTA
WE CAN USE?
I GOTTA ROLL IT OUT.
TO ORDER.
YES, TO ORDER.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS RIDICULOUSNESS.
HOMEMADE FETTUCCINE, AND THEN
RIGHT IN THE BOILING WATER.
TWO MINUTES.
PASTA'S READY.
AND THEN RIGHT INTO THE PAN.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
THE WATER DOESN'T HURT.
STIR THIS ALL AROUND,
PLACE THAT PASTA
IN THE CENTER,
AND THEN WE JUST POUR
EVERYTHING RIGHT OVER.
A LITTLE BIT OF FRESH CHOPPED
ITALIAN PARSLEY AT THE END.
OKAY, THIS
IS RIDICULOUS.
LOOK AT THIS.
OH, MY GOSH!
SHRIMP IS SUPER TENDER.
THOSE MUSHROOMS--
GREAT FLAVOR, HUH?
SO FRESH. THEY'RE JUST
ALL THROUGHOUT THAT SAUCE.
YOU GOING TO THE MARKET
JUST MAKES SUCH A DIFFERENCE.
YES.
THAT PRODUCE IS SO FRESH.
VEAL'S NICE AND TENDER.
THE CHICKEN'S ON POINT.
NOT A REAL THICK SAUCE,
JUST THICK ENOUGH TO HOLD ON.
I'VE GOTTA GET SOME
OF THIS FRESH PASTA.
MMM, I'M SO IMPRESSED, MAN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU ARE THE REAL DEAL.
HANDS DOWN, THE REAL DEAL.
RINO'S SPECIAL!
CHICKEN, VEAL.
PEOPLE HAVE FOUGHT
OVER THAT VEAL.
RINO'S SPECIAL.
THE MUSHROOM--
MMM, SO GOOD.
TRY THE VEAL.
IT'S THE BEST IN THE CITY.
DON'T FORGET TO TIP
YOUR WAITRESS.
(woman)
THAT'S RIGHT.
PORK TENDERLOIN.
I LOVE EVERYTHING
ABOUT RINO'S.
LINGUINE.
HOMEMADE HOME COOKING.
EXCELLENT.
ADD MY BRANDY.
THIS IS WHERE IT'S AT.
GIVE ME THE WHITE WINE--I GOTTA
ADD THE WHITE WINE TO THE CLAMS.
DUDE, I GOTTA TELL YOU, YOUR
PASSION FOR THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
THE FOOD ITSELF
IS BEYOND AMAZING.
FOR ME, THIS HAS BEEN LIKE
CULINARY DISNEYLAND.
IT WAS MY PLEASURE
ACTUALLY.
YOU'RE THE BEST, BUDDY.
OKAY.
THANK YOU.
THANKS, BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU'RE THE MAN.
YOU GOTTA COME
MEET THIS CAT.
NEXT STOP...
BUFFALO CHICKEN.
WE'RE HEADING
TO NEW JERSEY...
MY LIFE HAS CHANGED DRASTICALLY.
TO SEE WHAT'S NEW
WITH AN ORIGINAL
TRIPLE "D" FAVORITE.
ROUTE 189 BURGER UP!
I'VE HAD SO MANY DIFFERENT
STATES HERE--
MINNESOTA, FLORIDA, CALIFORNIA--
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
IT'S A SPECIAL KIND OF PLACE,
A SPECIAL GUY, SPECIAL FOOD.
SO A LOT OF PEOPLE
COME UP TO ME AND THEY SAY,
"HEY, GUY, WHAT HAPPENS
TO A JOINT AFTER YOU VISIT?"
WELL, HOW ABOUT I SHOW YOU?
LET'S GO BACK TO THE VERY FIRST
DINER WE EVER DID ON TRIPLE "D,"
THE BAYWAY DINER
IN LINDEN, NEW JERSEY.
EVERYTHING WAS GOOD?
MY LIFE HAS CHANGED DRASTICALLY.
THANK YOU.
MIKE GUINTA'S PLACE...
EXCUSE ME.
WAS PACKED TO START WITH.
...CHEESEBURGER.
NOW HE'S GOT FANS FLYING IN
FROM ALL OVER.
BUFFALO CHICKEN.
I'VE HAD SO MANY DIFFERENT
STATES HERE.
MINNESOTA, FLORIDA, CALIFORNIA--
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
I COME FROM THE CITY. THERE'S
MILLIONS OF DINERS IN THE CITY,
BUT THERE'S ONLY ONE
BAYWAY DINER.
LET'S ROCK 'N' ROLL.
IT'S BEEN AN ABSOLUTE
WHIRLWIND.
AND MIKE DIDN'T LET
THE OPPORTUNITY PASS HIM BY.
WE HAD SO MANY CUSTOMERS, I HAD
TO DO AN ADDITIONAL SEATING.
I LEFT THE DINER ORIGINAL.
I WANTED TO KEEP IT NINE STOOLS.
SO WE ADDED ON THIS TENT,
AND IT SEATS 11--
MORE THAN WHAT WE HAVE
IN THE DINER.
NOW MOST OF HIS REGULARS
CAME FROM THE REFINERY
ACROSS THE STREET...
LET'S GO.
THEN THE SECURITY RULES
WERE TIGHTENED.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT CHANGED
SOME REGULATIONS ABOUT
THE REFINERIES--THEY DIDN'T
WANT PEOPLE TO GO IN AND OUT.
BUT THAT DIDN'T
STOP MIKE...
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
SINCE THEY CAN'T COME TO ME,
WE JUST BRING IT TO THEM.
I HAD TO GO PURCHASE
A LUNCH TRUCK...
HOW'D YOU DO?
AND WE FILL THAT LUNCH TRUCK
UP HERE TWICE A DAY.
YOU DO WHATEVER
HAS TO BE DONE.
GOT TWO MORE.
AND THEN SOMEONE JUST ASKED ME
ONE TIME, "DO YOU DO CATERING?"
HE DOES NOW.
I'M THE TYPE OF GUY
THAT NEVER SAYS NO.
KIELBASA AND SAUERKRAUT.
I'VE EXPANDED INTO A FULL-BLOWN
CATERING COMPANY NOW.
YEAH, FULL-BLOWN...
YOU'RE ALL SET.
ONLY 100 GIGS A MONTH.
MY FAVORITE CATERING CLIENT
WOULD BE THE NEW YORK JETS.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
WE HAD TO PUT A 40-FOOT
STORAGE CONTAINER THERE.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE DID--
WE ADDED ELECTRIC,
AND THIS IS ALL
MY REFRIGERATION,
BECAUSE WE DON'T HAVE
TOO MUCH SPACE.
GOT MORE FOR ME?
AND WHAT ROOM HE DOES HAVE,
HE'S FILLING UP.
THE BASEMENT--
NOTHING'S CHANGED EXCEPT
A NEW CONVECTION OVEN,
AND A NEW CHEF.
THAT'D BE DANTE BARRA.
BUFFALO CHICKEN'S READY.
BUT MIKE HASN'T
LOST FOCUS...
THAT ONE'S GOOD, RIGHT?
ON WHAT STARTED IT ALL...
THANK YOU.
NINE STOOLS UPSTAIRS.
MASTER BURGER.
BAYWAY DINER JUST HAS
REALLY GOOD FOOD.
ALWAYS HAS.
THE FOOD'S GREAT.
EVERYTHING'S MADE FRESH.
JUST REALLY GOOD FOOD
MADE RIGHT THERE, YOU KNOW?
ROUTE 189 BURGER UP!
DELICIOUS. THOSE ONION RINGS
AND THE BARBECUE SAUCE--MMM.
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK UP.
GUY'S FAMOUS
FOR THE CHEESESTEAK.
THERE'S YOUR
MASTER BURGER. ENJOY.
THANK YOU.
WHERE YOU GONNA GET A BURGER
LIKE THIS? WOW. IT'S BLISS.
THIS IS WHAT A DINER
IS ABOUT. IT'S LIKE FAMILY.
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
YOU CAN'T EAT IT ALL?
MIKE MAKES YOU FEEL
COMFORTABLE WHEN YOU'RE HERE.
THIS IS IT, BROTHER.
THIS IS MY BABY.
IT'S NOT A JOB.
IT'S FUN TO COME HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA LAUGH.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE SOME FUN.
YOU MEET SOME PEOPLE.
IT'S A SPECIAL KIND OF PLACE,
A SPECIAL GUY, SPECIAL FOOD.
IT HAS BEEN A DREAM.
LIKE WE ALWAYS SAY,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
THESE RECIPES,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
ANYTHING RIGHT HERE?
FEELS LIKE
THERE'S SOMETHING...
WHERE WERE YOU
WITH THAT?