HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
FOR TURKEY AND STUFFING,
TRIPLE "D" STYLE.
IT'S A "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" THANKSGIVING.
AND WE'RE TAKING
THE HOLIDAY MEAL...
TURKEY STOCK HERE
JUST RUNS LIKE FINE WINE.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
HEY.
IN PORTLAND, MAINE...
I'LL COME OUT OF MY WAY
TO COME HERE.
WE'RE AT BECKY'S DINER...
THERE YOU GO.
WHERE THEY'RE PAIRING
THANKSGIVING STUFFIN'...
NICE.
WITH THE LOCAL CATCH.
EXCELLENT JOB.
RIGHT ON.
IN CAPE MAY, NEW JERSEY...
HOW'S IT GOING?
YOU GOOD?
IT'S GEORGE'S PLACE...
WE CELEBRATING THANKSGIVING
GREEK STYLE.
(all) OPA!
WHERE THE HOLIDAY MEAL
MEANS A GREEK FAVORITE...
LEG OF LAMB.
AND TURKEY GONE WILD.
TURKEY SUBMERGED
IN DUCK FAT.
AND IN NEW ORLEANS...
YOU CAN JUST COUNT ON COMING
HERE AND HAVING GOOD FOOD.
WE'RE AT SAMMY'S...
WE COOK EVERYTHING
HOMEMADE.
FOR TURKEY AND STUFFING...
TURKEY AND OYSTER
DRESSING.
NEW ORLEANS STYLE.
MMM. THAT'S
SUPER TASTY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON A "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" THANKSGIVING.
♪♪
IT'S THANKSGIVING SEASON
HERE ON TRIPLE "D,"
AND I KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING--
GUY'S GOTTA STUFF A TURKEY.
WELL, WE'RE HERE
IN PORTLAND, MAINE,
AND WE'RE NOT JUST
STUFFING TURKEY.
NO, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE'RE STUFFING LOBSTER.
THIS IS BECKY'S DINER
ON HOBSON'S WHARF.
BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER.
HERE ON THE DOCK,
WE KIND OF HAD TO HAVE
A DINER WITH A SEAFOOD FLARE.
HADDOCK CHOWDER.
BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER READY.
STUFFING SOMETHING
AT THANKSGIVING.
THAT'S LIKE THE STATE BIRD
HERE, ISN'T IT?
BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER UP.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
WHAT MAKES THEIRS
SO GOOD?
IT'S FRESH.
THANK YOU.
HAS BEEN, SINCE BECKY RAND
OPENED THE JOINT...
HOW WAS EVERYTHING?
ALMOST 20 YEARS AGO.
HOW'S THAT
MICKEY PANCAKE?
YOU HADN'T OWNED
A RESTAURANT BEFORE.
NO.
BUT YOU COOKED AT HOME.
I COOKED FOR SIX KIDS.
THIS IS THE TEAM.
AND THEY ALL PUT IN
THEIR TIME AT THE DINER.
MARK.
MARK, YOU WORK HERE.
IN THE WINTER, I COOK HERE,
IN THE SUMMER, FALL,
I'M ON THE BOAT,
CATCHING LOBSTERS.
AND HANDING 'EM OFF
TO STEPHANIE IN THE KITCHEN.
GOING ON LOBSTER.
WHO'S BEEN SERVING 'EM UP
SINCE SHE WAS 11 YEARS OLD.
BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER UP.
ALL OF THIS IS GONNA
GO INTO A LOBSTER?
YEAH.
WOW.
LUCKY LOBSTER.
MM-HMM.
BUTTER, SCALLOP,
SHRIMP, HADDOCK.
AND JUST EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL.
BUT WE'RE JUST GONNA LET
THIS SIT IN THERE, COOK DOWN,
AND BREAK
THAT HADDOCK APART.
YEAH, WHEN THE HADDOCK'S
ALL FLAKY,
IT'LL BE READY TO GO
INTO THE STUFFING.
AND THE STUFFING IS?
RITZ CRACKER CRUMBS,
A POUND OF BUTTER,
MAYONNAISE.
MMM. PARSLEY?
PARSLEY, YEAH, DRY MUSTARD,
SALT AND PEPPER,
AND SOME WORCES--
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
NICE.
CAN ALSO ADD THE CRAB MEAT,
SINCE IT'S ALREADY COOKED.
THAT MIX TOGETHER...
AND THE RECIPE
CAME FROM?
IT'S MY MOM'S RECIPE.
OKAY. ALL COOKED DOWN
AND READY TO ROLL?
YEAH, AND THE WATER FROM
THE SEAFOOD COOKING
WILL BE THE...
MOISTURIZER
INSIDE OF THIS.
NOW WE GO GET THOSE LOBSTERS
THAT YOUR BROTHER CAUGHT.
WE TAKE 'EM RIGHT OUT
OF THE TANK TO ORDER...
BRING 'EM IN HERE.
THAT FAST, THAT FRESH?
YEAH, YEAH.
WHOA!
BREAK 'EM OPEN A LITTLE BIT,
SO YOU CAN GET OUT
THE NICE TOMALLEY.
THE INNARDS
OF THE LOBSTER.
THIS ONE WE'RE GONNA OPEN UP
AND STUFF LIKE THIS?
YEAH. SQUEEZE SOME
OF THIS INSIDE.
STUFF IT WITH THE SEAFOOD
STUFFING WE JUST MADE.
LOOK AT THIS.
ALL THE WAY DOWN
TO THE TAIL.
AS MUCH AS WE CAN FIT IN.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA ROAST IN THE OVEN?
10, 15 MINUTES.
AT 350?
400.
HERE'S OUR LOBSTER.
LOOK AT THAT.
ISN'T THAT HOT?
WHOO, HOT.
HOW DO YOU GET INTO THIS?
IT'S BROKEN IN THE MIDDLE HERE,
SO YOU CAN REALLY GET DOWN
TO THE LOBSTER MEAT JUST WITH
A FORK THROUGH THE STUFFING.
YOU'VE GOTTA
BE KIDDING ME.
SO IT'S EVERYTHING THAT YOU
WANT A SEAFOOD STUFFING TO BE.
MMM. A LITTLE BIT SALTY,
NICE CRUNCH ON THE TOP,
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT
OF SEAFOOD FLAVOR.
THE REAL MORSEL THAT
I'M LOOKING FOR DOWN HERE
IS HOW TO GET INTO SOME
OF THAT--LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THAT IS SO TENDER
AND SO CREAMY.
DEEP, RICH FLAVOR.
EXCELLENT JOB.
RIGHT ON.
BAKED STUFFED LOBSTER.
THE STUFFING'S
INCREDIBLE.
SCALLOPS IN THERE, AND SOME
BREAD CRUMBS. IT'S DELICIOUS.
WE TELL EVERYONE
TO COME HERE.
IT'S ALL AUTHENTIC,
ALL HOMEMADE.
IT'S LIKE COMING TO YOUR
NEIGHBOR'S HOUSE FOR A MEAL.
ALL MY CUSTOMERS
FEEL LIKE FAMILY TO US.
THERE YOU GO.
SO SHE'S SERVING
'EM UP...
THANK YOU.
HER OWN FAMILY'S FAVORITES.
ALL AMERICAN
HOME-COOKED FOOD.
FROM LOCAL SEAFOOD...
THIS CHOWDER--LOADED
WITH FISH AND POTATOES.
TO DINER STANDARDS...
MEATLOAF DINNER READY.
AND OF COURSE,
THE THANKSGIVING CLASSIC.
TURKEY DINNER.
THIS ISN'T JUST
AT THANKSGIVING.
THIS IS ALL YEAR
AROUND. OHH!
ALL YEAR AROUND.
TURKEY WITH REAL GRAVY,
REAL MASHED POTATOES,
STUFFING WITH SAUSAGE.
REMINDS ME OF
A HOME-COOKED MEAL--SO GOOD.
WE'RE HAVING STUFFING FOR...
TURKEY DINNER.
WE'LL START WITH BUTTER.
A MESS OF ONIONS.
AND ABOUT THE SAME AMOUNT
OF CELERY AS ONIONS.
AND WE'RE JUST
GONNA SWEAT 'EM DOWN.
OH, YEAH. THEY'LL COOK
AGAIN IN THE OVEN.
ALL THE SAUSAGE
YOU JUST WANT TO BROWN UP.
WOW.
AND THAT'S ALL
BREAKFAST SAUSAGE?
YEAH.
OKAY.
WHILE THAT'S GOING ON...
WE'RE GONNA SEASON
THE BREAD.
POULTRY SEASONING,
SALT AND PEPPER.
THROW THIS IN HERE.
AND THAT'LL KIND OF
SOFTEN UP THE BREAD?
YEAH, THAT AND--
WOULD YOU LOOK AT THE GUNS
ON THIS GIRL?
OH, I KNOW, RIGHT?
WE CAN ARM WRESTLE LATER.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME STOCK INTO IT.
HOT STOCK OUT OF A GIGANTIC
STOCK POT.
IS THIS SANTA CLAUS' HOUSE?
NOW IT'S TIME TO MAKE...
GRAVY.
YEAH.
BUTTER, ONIONS.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE ROUX.
WE'LL PROBABLY ADD SOME FLOUR
AND SALT AND PEPPER.
WE'RE PROBABLY
GONNA ADD SOME?
WE MOST CERT--
HOW DO YOU WANT
TO THICKEN IT UP ANYWAY?
WE MOST CERTAINLY WILL.
SALT AND PEPPER.
SO COOK IT DOWN, MAKE THE ROUX.
ARE WE READY TO ADD THE STOCK?
YES.
TURKEY STOCK HERE JUST RUNS
LIKE FINE WINE.
KEGGER! (whistles)
GIVE A LITTLE STIR
ON THAT?
YEAH, PLEASE.
I CAN DOUBLE DUTY.
I GOT IT.
SO IT'S KIND OF
AN ONION GRAVY OF SORTS?
YEAH.
MMM.
THE STOCK
IS JUST ROCK STAR.
IT'S ROCK STAR STOCK.
WE BRINED THE TURKEY
24 HOURS.
THIS IS A BIG BIRD.
IT IS, ABOUT 25 POUNDS.
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED
TO GO TO THE GYM.
NOW IT'S TIME
TO STUFF THE BIRD.
YES. I'M GONNA THROW
SOME SALT AND PEPPER ON IT.
AND THEN NOW
YOU'RE GOING TO...
MANEUVER IT
INTO THE BAG.
PUT IT IN THE BAG.
WRAPPIN' IT UP.
THERE WE GO.
GONNA SHIP THIS
TO YOU.
OVEN'S PREHEATED.
350.
FOR HOW LONG?
THREE AND A HALF
TO FOUR HOURS.
IT'S READY TO GO.
(whistles)
SERVE IT UP.
YOU CUT AGAINST THE GRAIN OF
THE TURKEY. SOME STUFFING, TOO.
THIS A NORMAL PORTION?
YEAH.
SERIOUSLY? YOU MAKE
THE MASHED, TOO?
OH, YEAH. WHAT DO YOU LIKE
GRAVY ON--EVERYTHING?
HIT IT.
AND THE STUFFING?
OH, OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
SKIN'S AWESOME.
THE TURKEY
IS VERY SIMPLY DONE.
NATURAL FLAVOR OF THE BIRD WITH
JUST A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
COOKING IN THE BAG,
I THINK, REALLY KEEPS
THE NATURAL JUICES IN THERE.
THE MEDLEY OF IT GOING TOGETHER
WITH KIND OF THIS
ONION GRAVY IS GREAT.
HONESTLY, THE STUFFING
IS MY FAVORITE.
THE BREAD--GOT
SUCH GREAT TEXTURE TO IT,
AND THE MASHED POTATOES
ARE AS CREAMY AS THEY GET.
HAPPY THANKSGIVING.
TURKEY DINNER FOR YOU.
HEAVEN ON A PLATE.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE GRAVY.
IT WAS REALLY GOOD.
THE STUFFING IS EXCELLENT.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF
THANKSGIVING ON MY PLATE,
AND I DIDN'T HAVE
TO COOK IT.
CHOCOLATE CREAM PIE.
EVERYTHING I TRIED
WAS GOOD.
LOBSTER ROLL.
BEST LOBSTER ROLLS
IN TOWN.
FRIED CLAMS.
I'LL COME OUT OF MY WAY
TO COME HERE.
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
THEY MAKE YOU FEEL
LIKE YOU'RE AT HOME.
I WANT TO KNOW HOW TO GET
ON THE THANKSGIVING LIST...
I'LL SAVE A CHAIR
FOR YOU.
IT'S JUST LORI, ME,
RYDER, AND HUNTER.
I MEAN, SO JUST FOUR MORE.
WE CAN SIT IN THE GARAGE.
WE CAN FIT YOU IN.
UP NEXT ON
A TRIPLE "D" THANKSGIVING...
PICK UP, MEAT LOAF.
WE'RE HEADING TO JERSEY...
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD HERE.
WHERE IT'S TURKEY...
WHY NOT TURKEY CONFIT?
OVER THE TOP.
THANKSGIVING WILL NEVER
BE THE SAME AT YOUR HOUSE.
SO HERE I AM IN CAPE MAY,
EXIT 0,
THE LAST EXIT
ON THE GARDEN STATE PARKWAY.
NOW THIS SHORE TOWN IS KNOWN
FOR ITS VICTORIAN HOMES
AND AS A GREAT FAMILY
VACATION DESTINATION.
NOW RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF IT ALL,
ON THE CORNER
OF BEACH AND PERRY,
IS A 42-YEAR-OLD
NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
THAT'S SERVING UP BREAKFAST,
LUNCH, AND DINNER
WITH A LITTLE GREEK TWIST.
THIS IS GEORGE'S PLACE.
EVEN THOUGH THESE DAYS...
HOW'S IT GOING?
YOU GOOD?
JOHN AND PETE
ARE RUNNING THE JOINT...
PASS IT DOWN
WHEN IT'S READY.
THE KARAPANAGIOTIS BROTHERS,
HEY!
DOING WHAT A LOT OF GREEK
FAMILIES DO COME NOVEMBER.
GOOD OVER HERE.
WE CELEBRATE THANKSGIVING
GREEK STYLE.
(all) OPA!
WHAT HAPPENS AT THANKSGIVING
IN A GREEK FAMILY?
YOU HAVE THE TURKEY,
THEN WE GET A BIG LEG OF LAMB.
THIS IS YOUR LAMB.
THANKSGIVING DAY SPECIAL--
ROASTED LEG OF LAMB.
FAMILY RECIPE.
LAMB HERE IS EXCELLENT.
HOW WE GONNA PREPARE IT?
PIERCE IT A FEW TIMES.
YOU'RE GONNA JAM A LITTLE
GARLIC CLOVE IN THERE.
YEP.
SO THIS IS OLD-SCHOOL
GREEK-STYLE LEG OF LAMB.
YES, YES.
THERE WE GO. A LITTLE
SALT, PEPPER, OREGANO.
GIVE IT A RUB DOWN,
PUT A LITTLE WATER.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT STEAM
WILL HELP EXPEDITE
THE COOKING PROCESS.
A LITTLE FRESH OREGANO,
FRESH THYME.
WRAP IT IN FOIL.
OKAY, WE'RE GOOD.
IN THE OVEN
3 1/2 HOURS.
400 DEGREES.
PULL IT OUT.
AND THEN TAKE OFF
THE FOIL.
LET IT BROWN.
CARAMELIZE
THE OUTSIDE OF IT.
BEAUTIFUL ROASTED LEG
OF LAMB.
LET IT REST
A LITTLE BIT.
JUST SLICE A LITTLE BIT
DOWN FOR YOU.
GO RIGHT ONTO
THE FLATTOP GRILL,
NO OIL OR NOTHIN'.
A LITTLE SEAR ON IT.
WHILE THAT DOES ITS THING,
PUT OUR ROASTED RED PEPPER
AND EGGPLANT ORZO.
KIND OF LIKE
A STAPLE STARCH.
YES. RIGHT THERE.
TZATZIKI SAUCE--
CUCUMBER, GARLIC, YOGURT.
OF COURSE YOU NEED
THAT ON THE SIDE.
OF COURSE. SNOW PEA CHUTES.
THIS IS OUR...
IT'S A LEMON, OREGANO,
OLIVE OIL--
AND DRIED OREGANO.
GOTTA TELL YOU, MAN,
TASTY DISH.
THAT'S ABOUT AS GREEK
AS THEY COME, BRO.
YEAH.
MADE THE RIGHT WAY,
AND THE LEMON, GARLIC, OLIVE OIL
WITH THE OREGANO...
YEAH.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
DOES IT? NICE.
OH, REALLY NICE.
THANK YOU.
GREAT JOB, BRO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LEG OF LAMB.
HOW'S THE LAMB?
THE LAMB'S AWESOME.
(woman) PERFECTLY DONE,
TENDER.
LOVE THE SAUCE. MELTS IN YOUR
MOUTH. IT'S JUST SO AMAZING.
CHICKEN GYRO IN THE WINDOW.
EVERYTHING IS GREAT HERE.
YOU ALWAYS FEEL GOOD
IF YOU COME HERE TO EAT.
YOU LIKE THAT?
YEAH.
JOHN ALWAYS HAS A SMILE.
HE'S ALWAYS LOVING
AND FUN.
AND HE'S BEEN HEADLINING
HERE...
IS THE SERVICE HERE
ANY GOOD?
SINCE HE TOOK OVER FOR HIS
FATHER IN-LAW GEORGE
ALMOST EIGHT YEARS AGO.
DIDN'T REALIZE HOW MUCH
I LIKED THE GREEK FOOD,
BEFORE JOHN
CHANGED THE MENU.
PUT A LITTLE MORE GREEK
INFLUENCE TO IT.
(all) OPA!
AND PUT HIS BROTHER PETE
IN THE KITCHEN.
(bell dings)
HE HAS AN ORIGINAL TOUCH.
A BLEND OF HIS FAMILY'S
GREEK RECIPES...
FETA CHEESE.
AND YEARS OF COOKING
AT FINE DINING RESTAURANTS.
PICK UP, MEAT LOAF.
THERE'S A SMOKED
FIG KETCHUP ON TOP--
PETER'S SPECIAL RECIPE.
MMM.
AND FOR THANKSGIVING...
ENJOY.
ON TOP OF THE LAMB...
I NEED A TURKEY...
HE'S GOT HIS OWN TAKE
ON THE AMERICAN CLASSIC.
YOU THINK YOU'RE GETTING
TURKEY AND STUFFING,
AND WHAT YOU'RE GETTING
IS A WHOLE LOT MORE.
TURKEY CONFIT.
SUBMERGED IN DUCK FAT.
IT'S GREAT.
WHERE DID YOU COME UP
WITH THIS IDEA?
THANKSGIVING CAME AROUND,
AND WAS LIKE, WHAT ELSE
CAN WE DO WITH THE TURKEY?
WHY NOT TURKEY CONFIT?
SO HOW DO WE
START THIS?
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT RUNNING
THROUGH THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
A LITTLE?
YEAH, JUST A LITTLE.
TARRAGON, ROSEMARY,
PARSLEY.
ITALIAN FLAT-LEAF.
AND WHAT DO WE CALL THIS
MIXTURE THAT YOU'RE MAKING?
GREEN SALT.
THERE YOU GO.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S LIKE A SAVORY SNOW CONE.
OH, THAT IS AWESOME.
I AM SO STEALING THIS.
THAT GREEN SALT RIGHT THERE
IS GONNA GET RUBBED
ON THE TURKEY BREAST?
YES, IT IS.
SKIN ON AND EVERYTHING?
YEP, SKIN ON.
GO FOR IT.
I DON'T WANT TO PUT
TOO MUCH ON THERE,
'CAUSE THEN IT'S GONNA
GET OVER-SALTED.
PUT THIS IN THE FRIDGE
FOR TWO TO THREE HOURS,
WASH IT OFF WITH SOME
COOL WATER.
BACK INTO THE FRIDGE
FOR 24 HOURS,
AND THEN WE GO
TO THE CONFIT.
THAT'S CORRECT.
SUBMERGE THESE TURKEY BREASTS
INTO DUCK FAT. I LIKE THIS.
A CROSS BETWEEN DEEP-FRYING
AND POACHING.
IN THE OVEN AT 250
FOR 3 HOURS.
YES.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS WITH?
CORN BREAD AND ANDOUILLE
SAUSAGE STUFFING.
OKAY. CORN BREAD
FOR THE STUFFING.
CORNMEAL, ALL PURPOSE FLOUR,
BAKING SODA.
BAKING SODA
AND BAKING POWDER.
CORRECT.
GIVES IT TWO DIFFERENT
LEAVENING TIMES.
SUGAR, KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE BLENDED OLIVE OIL.
THAT'S ITALIAN
OLIVE OIL.
WHAT?
FOUR EGGS, BUTTERMILK.
SO ALL OF THIS
CORN BREAD EFFORT
IS JUST TO MAKE CORN BREAD
TO MAKE INTO STUFFING?
CORRECT.
THAT WAS QUICK.
VERY NICE.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
25 MINUTES.
PULL IT OUT, LET IT COOL,
AND THEN WE START
MAKING STUFFING.
THEN WE FLIP IT OUT.
OH, YOU SHOULD SMELL THAT.
TAKE OUT SOME PIECES,
AND JUST, LARGE BREAKS.
POUR IT RIGHT
ONTO A SHEET PAN.
BACK IN THE OVEN 15 MINUTES?
YEP.
NOW IT'S TIME TO MAKE
THE SAVORY FOR THE STUFFING.
BLENDED OIL. NOT SURE
IF IT'S ITALIAN OR GREEK.
PUT THAT RIGHT IN THERE.
ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
COOK THE ANDOUILLE DOWN.
YOU WANT TO GET THAT FLAVOR
IN THE OIL.
SPANISH ONIONS, GREEN PEPPER,
CELERY, CARROTS, GARLIC.
GREEK OREGANO.
GREEK OREGANO, YES.
THERE YOU GO. ALL RIGHT,
OVER HERE? I GOTCHA.
SPOTTING HIM.
COLD CHICKEN STOCK. COOL IT
DOWN, SO WHEN WE ADD THE EGGS...
GETS 'EM IN THERE REAL QUICK,
STIRS 'EM UP--
DUDE KNOWS
WHAT HE'S DOING.
AND THEN OUR CORN BREAD.
LOOK AT THESE. THEY TURN INTO
FULL-ON CROUTON EL NUGGET-O'S.
SUCK IN ALL THAT
CHICKEN STOCK.
NOW WE GO
ONTO ANOTHER TRAY.
HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA GO IN THE OVEN?
ABOUT 20, 25 MINUTES,
GET IT BROWN ON THE TOP.
ALL RIGHT, TURKEY BREAST.
WE'LL JUST BREAK OFF
A BIG PIECE.
WE'RE JUST GETTING IT A LITTLE
BIT DARKER ON THE ONE SIDE.
LOOK AT THE SHRED-O-TURKEY.
HEY, PETE, SOMEBODY AT THE DOOR!
MMM. IT'S NOT SUPER DUCKY.
THAT'S NOT WHAT
IT'S "QUACKED" UP TO BE.
LET'S GET THAT STUFFING.
THERE WE GO.
LET'S GIVE IT A QUICK SLICE.
PIECE RIGHT THERE
RIGHT ON THE CENTER,
TURKEY COMING OFF THE GRILL,
RIGHT ON THERE WITH IT.
AND FINALLY, CRANBERRIES--SIMPLE
SYRUP AND A LITTLE BIT OF HONEY,
AND MY TRUSTY SNOW PEA CHUTES.
PUT A SPIN ON THE CLASSICS.
MMM.
THIS IS DEFINITELY
A TURKEY DINNER GONE WILD.
NICE.
SAVORY, SWEET, SALTY,
THEN YOU GET THE ACID
FROM THE CRANBERRY.
YOU'VE GOT THAT COMPLEXITY.
IT'S VERY CONTEMPORARY.
IT'S GOT ITS COMPONENTS
OF OLD SCHOOL
WITH WHAT I WILL
HONESTLY SAY, DUDE,
IS THE BOMB DRESSING.
MMM.
TURKEY CONFIT.
THE TURKEY
IS JUST SO TENDER.
(woman) TASTES LIKE IT'S BEEN
BASTING IN THE OVEN FOREVER.
STUFFING REALLY ADDS
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICINESS.
ACTUALLY, IT'S A NICE TWIST.
PICK UP, LAMB CHOPS.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD HERE.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
DOING RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE WRITING THIS DOWN,
BECAUSE YOU'RE GONNA GO BUY
2 GALLONS OF DUCK FAT.
THANKSGIVING WILL NEVER
BE THE SAME AT YOUR HOUSE
AFTER HANGING OUT
WITH THIS GUY.
NEXT UP ON OUR
TRIPLE "D" THANKSGIVING...
TURKEY DINNER.
WE'RE HEADED
TO NEW ORLEANS...
MMM.
WHERE THE BIG BIRD...
NOW I'M GONNA GET
OUR OYSTERS PREPPED.
THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU SEE EVERYDAY.
IS GOING BIG EASY.
REALLY TASTE THE OYSTERS.
MMM. DUDE.
SO I'M HERE IN NEW ORLEANS,
ON ELYSION FIELDS AVENUE,
RIGHT BETWEEN I-10
AND I-610.
NOW WHEN I'M THINKING
OF GREAT FOOD IN THIS AREA--
AND THERE'S A LOT OF IT--
I GOTTA BE HONEST,
I'M NOT THINKING
ABOUT THANKSGIVING--
WELL, THAT'S UNTIL I HEARD ABOUT
SAMMY'S FOOD SERVICE & DELI.
TURKEY DINNER WORKING,
COMING UP.
IT'S JUST A WONDERFUL
NEW ORLEANS LOCAL RESTAURANT.
TURKEY DINNER.
DOING A KILLER
NEW ORLEANS THANKSGIVING.
MMM.
THANKSGIVING IS
BIG-TIME IN NEW ORLEANS.
COMING UP.
AND IT'S A HUGE TRADITION
FOR SELF-TAUGHT CHEF
SAMMY SCHLOEGEL.
WE COOK EVERYTHING
HOMEMADE.
AT A JOINT THAT USED TO BE HIS
UNCLE'S BUTCHER SHOP...
TURKEY DINNER FOR HERE.
UNTIL SAMMY AND HIS WIFE GINA
TOOK OVER.
TURKEY AND OYSTER
DRESSING.
BUTCHER SHOP TURNS
INTO A SANDWICH SHOP.
NOW IT TURNS INTO MAKING
SOME THANKSGIVING...
AND THANKSGIVING
IN THE BIG EASY MEANS THESE.
I KNOW THESE
AS CHAYOTE.
WE CALL THEM MIRLITON.
MIL-I-TON, MIRLITON.
MIRLITONS.
IT'S A VERY COMMON VEGETABLE
THAT YOU CAN GET
IN NEW ORLEANS
OVER THANKSGIVING.
AND THEY'RE USING 'EM
IN SOUP.
SEAFOOD MIRLITON SOUP--
PEOPLE GO CRAZY OVER THIS.
THEY START ORDERING IT
A COUPLE WEEKS AHEAD OF TIME.
REALLY?
YEAH.
KINDA BOIL 'EM
LIKE WE DO A POTATO.
YES. PURéE 'EM.
IT HAS A LOT OF GOOD
CAJUN SPICES.
IT'S LOADED WITH SHRIMP
AND CRAB.
SEAFOOD SQUASH SOUP
FOR THANKSGIVING.
IT'S WEIRD.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
GREAT TEXTURE.
DEFINITELY HAS THE SEAFOOD,
CHOWDER KIND OF FLAVOR
TO IT. MMM.
I SEE WHY PEOPLE
LOVE IT.
SEAFOOD MIRLITON SOUP.
TO DIE.
IT IS SO GOOD.
AND THAT'S JUST
THE FIRST COURSE.
MMM.
FOR THE REST
OF THE THANKSGIVING MEAL,
WHAT ELSE?
WONDERFUL TURKEY
AND CRANBERRY. MMM.
DONE THE BIG EASY WAY.
DRESSING WITH OYSTERS.
THIS IS NEW ORLEANS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE OYSTERS.
THAT'S THE WAY IT IS.
ALL RIGHT, GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN.
GET OUR BED SET UP FOR
OUR TURKEY TO LAY ON.
CELERY, GARLIC,
COARSELY CHOPPED ONIONS.
THESE ARE ALSO GONNA CREATE
A LOT OF GREAT FLAVOR
FOR A GRAVY LATER.
ABSOLUTELY.
PAINT 'EM UP
WITH GARLIC BUTTER OIL.
IT'S GONNA GIVE 'EM
A NICE SHEEN,
MAKE THIS POULTRY SEASONING
STICK TO 'EM.
TRY NOT TO MISS
ANY SPOTS.
I THINK YOU MIGHT HAVE
MISSED THERE.
THERE YOU GO.
GOOD JOB.
THERE WE GO.
DID YOU MAKE
THE CHICKEN STOCK?
FROM THE CHICKEN BACKS.
IT'S A SANDWICH SHOP.
PUT IT IN THERE.
SO THAT'S GONNA MAKE SOME
GREAT GRAVY ON THE BOTTOM.
STUFFING TIME.
1/2 POUND OF BUTTER. WE'RE
GONNA MAKE A BéCHAMEL SAUCE.
BéCHAMEL FOR STUFFING?
SOME FLOUR.
A LITTLE ROUX.
A LITTLE MILK IN THERE.
NICE LITTLE CREAMY
PASTE HERE.
SAUTé SOME CELERY,
RED BELL PEPPERS,
ONIONS, GREEN BELL PEPPER.
I'M GONNA NEED A SPOON.
LISTEN, I JUST SHOWED UP
WITH CAR KEYS.
OH, I'M TELLIN' YA.
HOW YOU LIKE
THEM APPLES?
PLEASE DON'T ASK
FOR A MIXER.
PUT OUR BUTTER IN.
SWEAT THE VEGGIES
A LITTLE BIT,
BUTTER'S KIND OF HELPING 'EM
MELLOW OUT.
TAKE OUR OYSTERS,
PUT 'EM IN THIS
LITTLE CHOPPIN' MACHINE.
BREAK 'EM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU SEE EVERY DAY.
RELEASES SOME
OF THE FLAVOR.
HUGE.
ADD SOME OF THIS GARLIC HERE,
THE THYME.
WHAT WAS THAT WORD?
THYME.
THYME. RED PEPPER FLAKES,
BLACK PEPPER,
SOME CAJUN SEASONING,
BAY LEAVES,
CHICKEN BASE.
SMELLS VERY--LOOK
AT THE AMOUNT OF OYSTERS
TO THE AMOUNT OF BREAD.
THIS GUY IS CRAZY.
HEY.
YOU HAVE THE FRENCH BREAD
BROUGHT IN.
YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD, EVEN STALE.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
I KNOW THIS IS THE PART
YOU'VE BEEN WAITIN' FOR.
PUT THE BéCHAMEL
IN HERE NOW.
YOU'RE BUILDING A GRAVY
RIGHT INTO THE STUFFING.
HERE WE GO
WITH THE OYSTERS.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL THAT IN.
I WANT THAT OVER SOME PASTA.
FORGET PUTTING IT IN STUFFING.
GRATED PARMESAN, TOUCH OF
LEMON JUICE, FLAT-LEAF PARSLEY.
CAN I JUST START DIPPING
THE BREAD IN IT,
AND FORGET THE WHOLE
THANKSGIVING THING?
CERTAINLY, ABSOLUTELY.
IS THAT YOUR 5 BUCKS
ON THE FLOOR OVER THERE?
OH, MAN, MY LUCKY DAY--
LOOK AT THIS--
SO WORTH 5 BUCKS.
THIS HAS JUST
GOTTA BE A DIP
WITH SOME BREAD--
THAT'S A THOUGHT,
EXACTLY.
AND THE OYSTERS ARE FRESH?
OYSTERS ARE FRESH,
AND WE HAVE FIVE EGGS
BEATEN HERE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT!
BEFORE YOU PUT
THE EGGS IN IT, MAN.
NOW I'M GONNA
FOLD THIS IN.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
THAT IS RIDICULOUSLY
FANTASTIC.
GET A BAKE ON IT.
PRECOOKING THIS,
LET THOSE EGGS COOK.
OUT OF THE OVEN,
INTO THAT BIRD.
STUFFING THE BIRD.
TUCK HIS LEGS IN.
GIVE HIM A LITTLE TRUSS.
BIRD'S GONNA GO IN, 350.
HOUR AND A HALF.
CORRECT. NOW IT'S TIME
TO MAKE OUR GRAVY.
'CAUSE YOU ALREADY FORTIFIED IT
WITH SOME CHICKEN STOCK.
TURN THIS BOAT MOTOR
LOOSE.
HAVE A LITTLE TEXTURE TO IT.
HERE WE GO. GO AHEAD AND CUT
THIS BREAST LOBE OFF OF HERE.
I DON'T REALLY THINK IT'S FAIR
THAT I SHOULD HAVE ALL THAT.
FEEL FREE TO SHARE.
THE SEASONING
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THIS,
ALONG WITH THAT
GARLIC BUTTER RUB YOU DID--
THAT'S GOOD BIRD, MAN.
PUT IT ON A PLATE HERE.
DID YOU MAKE
THE CRANBERRIES?
YEAH. THIS IS WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR RIGHT HERE.
RIGHT OUT OF THE BIRD.
A LITTLE TOPPING
OF THE GRAVY.
MMM.
DUDE, THAT'S SUPER TASTY.
WOW. THE TURKEY
IS RIDICULOUSLY TENDER.
THE STUFFING HAS GREAT
TEXTURE TO IT.
AND THAT'S BIG FLAVOR. YOU CAN
REALLY TASTE THE OYSTERS--
A BOATLOAD OF 'EM--
AND THE GRAVY
IS RIGHT ON POINT
UP AT RIDICULOUS LEVEL.
THIS IS LIKE
FOOD MARDI GRAS RIGHT HERE.
THERE YOU GO.
(woman) TURKEY DINNER.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THE DRESSING IS DELICIOUS.
(woman)
YOU TASTE THE OYSTERS.
OH, YEAH.
PERFECT THANKSGIVING MEAL.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU DO
THANKSGIVING RIGHT
IN NEW ORLEANS?
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
MMM.
SO ALL THAT TURKEY IN THE SOUP,
WHAT COULD WE DO NEXT?
WHEN WE COME BACK TO SAMMY'S
HERE IN NEW ORLEANS,
WE ARE GONNA TRY
A THANKSGIVING DESSERT
THAT MAY EVEN SURPRISE ME.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
TURKEY DINNER FOR HERE.
AT SAMMY'S FOOD SERVICE
IN NEW ORLEANS...
HERE YOU GO.
THANKSGIVING DINNER COMES
WITH A DELTA TWIST.
COMING UP.
FROM SOUP...
SEAFOOD MIRLITON SOUP.
TO TURKEY AND DRESSING.
YOU TASTE THE OYSTERS
IN THE OYSTER DRESSING.
PICK UP!
AND FOR DESSERT...
PUMPKIN BREAD PUDDING?
PUMPKIN BREAD PUDDING--
ESPECIALLY AROUND THANKSGIVING,
YOU GOTTA HAVE IT.
YOU KNOW WHEN IT STARTS OFF
WITH THIS, MAKES ME HAPPY.
A MESS OF EGGS.
MESS OF EGGS.
WHIPPING CREAM.
GET IN THERE!
YEAH.
BROWN SUGAR,
SOME WHITE SUGAR.
ROASTED PURéE PUMPKIN.
AND THEN WE HAVE
SOME PUMPKIN SPICE.
NECESSARY.
SOME VANILLA.
VANILLA.
VANILLA BEAN.
SCRAPINGS OF
THE VANILLA BEANS.
YES. PURéE
EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
BIG PUMPKIN OMELET
RIGHT THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW SOME FRENCH BREAD.
SO YOU TAKE THE FRENCH BREAD
THAT'S LEFT OVER,
GRIND IT UP,
CRUST AND ALL.
YES, AND WE JUST
POUR THAT RIGHT IN.
WOW, YOU GUYS
GET SERIOUS ABOUT THIS.
THIS WILL SIT FOR MAYBE
20 MINUTES...
OKAY.
JUST TO ABSORB
ALL THE LIQUID.
INTO THE BIG CHUNKS
OF BREAD.
WHAT ARE THESE LITTLE
TASTY MORSELS?
THOSE ARE CANDIED WALNUTS...
OH, HO HO.
JUST TO ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF FLAVOR TO IT.
OH, OF COURSE--NICE
LITTLE TEXTURE IN THERE.
AND THEN I'M GONNA NEED
THAT PAN RIGHT THERE.
OOH!
THERE YOU GO. (whistles)
DOWN RIGHT DOWN
TO THE NUMBER, HUH?
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT AT 300.
DOWN FOR AN HOUR.
YOU BRING A LOT
OF THAT MOISTURE OUT,
JUST SITS THERE
AND COMPACTS DOWN.
THAT'S CRAZY. I LIKE THESE
LITTLE CANDIED WALNUTS.
I JUST PICKED THAT
OUT OF THERE.
WOULD YOU LIKE
A SLICE?
LET IT COOL DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
THESE CANDIED WALNUTS TASTE
LIKE PUMPKIN PIE.
I'M NOT A BIG BREAD PUDDING FAN,
I GOTTA BE HONEST WITH YOU.
NO?
NO, IT'S THE EGG RATIO.
IT'S NOT NECESSARY.
SHOULD BE ABLE TO PUT
SOMETHING ELSE IN THERE--
CHICKEN STOCK
WOULD BE GOOD.
OH, OKAY, WELL, WE'RE GONNA
SEE IF YOU LIKE THIS.
I'M A FAN OF THIS
BREAD COMPANY,
SO I GOTTA BELIEVE THAT WITH
THE BREAD BEING CHEWY AND ALL--
OH, IT'S WONDERFUL.
RUM SAUCE--
CREAM, SUGAR, RUM,
CORNSTARCH.
HOW DO YOU THINK
I SHOULD GET AFTER IT?
ATTACK IT
FROM THE LEFT?
GONNA GO RIGHT
IN THE CENTER.
LOOK AT THAT.
SMELLS LIKE PUMPKIN PIE.
I'M GONNA BE EATING
THESE WORDS FOR A WHILE.
THAT IS SOME
TASTY BREAD PUDDING.
IT'S GOT GOOD CRUNCH.
IT'S NOT PUMPKIN MADNESS.
THE RUM SAUCE ISN'T
SUPER OVER-THE-TOP SWEET.
COULD BE THE HOLIDAYS
OR WHAT,
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT COMBO THAT--
I JUST ATE FOUR MORE BITES
THAN I EXPECTED I WOULD.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
PUMPKIN BREAD PUDDING.
IT'S JUST FABULOUS.
PUMPKIN-Y, NICE CREAM SAUCE.
OH, IT'S YUMMY.
MIRLITON SOUP.
ANYTHING THAT THEY PUT
TOGETHER IS EXCELLENT. MMM.
YOU CAN JUST COUNT ON COMING
HERE AND HAVING GOOD FOOD.
OH, YEAH.
MY BROTHER FROM ANOTHER MOTHER.
GOATEE, SOME EARRINGS,
BLEACH THAT HAIR, I'LL HAVE HIM
WORKING AS MY DOUBLE.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU DRIVE THE '67 AROUND, I'LL
HANG OUT AND MAKE SANDWICHES.
OH, YOU GOT
A DEAL THERE.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THE "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" THANKSGIVING.
TO CHECK OUT THESE GREAT HOLIDAY
RECIPES, GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF THAT EVER MAKES IT
IN THE SHOW, I'LL KILL YOU.