HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOA, JUST LIKE
AT THE FAIR.
IT'S A BIG, OLD SLICE
OF AMERICANA.
TIMELESS...
WOW.
IN CAMBRIDGE, MASSACHUSETTS...
CHICKEN KABOB.
THE CORNER FAVORITE...
VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHERE A COUPLE OF BROTHERS...
CHICKEN GYRO
WITH EVERYTHING.
ARE CRANKIN' OUT
THE GREEK CLASSICS...
READY.
THEY GREW UP WITH.
MMM.
THIS IS A REAL
MEAT ATTACK.
IN NASHVILLE...
GOT A CRAB PO' BOY READY.
THE LOCAL JOINT...
THE FOOD IS JUST OUTRAGEOUS.
BRINGIN' A TASTE
OF THE BAYOU...
NOW THERE WE GO.
TO A WHOLE NEW CROWD.
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE, YOU
DON'T NORMALLY THINK OF CAJUN.
WOW. I CAN'T GET IT IN
FAST ENOUGH.
AND IN
SILVER SPRING, MARYLAND...
CHICKEN POTPIE.
THE GENERAL STORE...
THEY PUT SOME LOVE
INTO THIS FOOD.
WHERE THEY'RE SERVIN' UP
A TRUE TASTE...
CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
BEST FRIED CHICKEN
YOU EVER HAD.
OF YESTERDAY...
MMM.
(chuckles)
THE AMOUNT OF HOT SAUCE
YOU PUT IN THAT OWNS IT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO WE'RE BACK IN BOSTON.
WELL, NOT ACTUALLY BOSTON.
WE'RE IN CAMBRIDGE,
ABOUT 2 MILES NORTHWEST
OF HARVARD UNIVERSITY.
BUT WE LOVE SHOOTIN'
TRIPLE "D" IN THIS AREA.
I MEAN, WE HAVE HIT
SOME DOOZIES,
STARTIN' OFF WITH KELLY'S DINER,
MIKE'S CITY DINER,
SAM LAGRASSA'S,
BARTLEY'S BURGER COTTAGE.
I MEAN, JUST TO NAME A FEW,
AND WE GOT A NEW ONE
TO PUT ON THE LIST--
THIS JOINT, THE GREEK CORNER.
SOUVLAKI PLATE, PICK UP.
EXCELLENT GREEK FOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
CHICKEN KABOB.
IS THIS REAL GREEK
IN YOUR OPINION?
YEAH, THAT'S REAL GREEK.
SO ARE THESE GUYS.
SWORDFISH KABOB.
GEORGE
AND THEMIS BORETOS...
MOUSSAKA, PICK UP.
TWO BROTHERS WHO LEFT
GREECE TO GO TO COLLEGE...
CHICKEN GYRO
WITH EVERYTHING.
AND ENDED UP COOKING...
WHAT YEAR DID YOU
OPEN THE RESTAURANT?
1989.
AND STARTED SERVIN' UP
MOM'S RECIPES...
(woman) BAKED LAMB.
TO THE CAMBRIDGE CROWD.
I TRIED THE MOUSSAKA,
AND IT WAS REALLY GOOD.
LAMB KABOB.
LAMB SHISH-KEBAB.
IT'S FABULOUS.
CHICKEN GYRO.
IT'S REAL MEAT, AND THE GYROS
ARE ON THIS THING.
GYRO COMING.
A LOT OF GREEK RESTAURANTS
HAVE THE FORMED CONE FROZEN.
BUT FEW HAVE THIS.
IT'S ALL MADE FRESH.
REAL MEAT?
REAL MEAT.
GYRO SANDWICH.
WAY ABOVE
WHAT YOU WOULD EXPECT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE BEEF
AND LAMB GYRO.
FIRST THE BEEF.
THIS IS THE BRISKET.
THINLY SLICED,
AGAINST THE GRAIN.
BECAUSE IF YOU CUT IT
THE OTHER WAY...
CHEWY.
PUT SOME LAMB.
THIS IS LAMB LEG.
GOT IT.
WE MARINATE IT--SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, FRESH GARLIC,
GARLIC POWDER.
NICE. A LOT OF GARLIC
FLAVOR IN THIS.
PAPRIKA AND GREEK YOGURT.
OH, I LIKE GREEK YOGURT.
NICE AND TANGY.
SOME WINE?
RED WINE AND EXTRA
VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
(whistles)
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MIX THE...
YOU'RE GONNA GET CRAZY
WITH IT, AREN'T YOU?
YES.
YOU CAN DO THIS, MAN.
GET SASSY WITH IT.
OWN IT. COME ON,
DANIEL-SAN. OKAY, YOU GOT 'EM.
NOW MARINATE
FOR 24 HOURS.
OKAY.
TELL ME YOU ARE NOT EXCITED.
I KNOW YOU'RE OUT THERE
RIGHT NOW GETTIN' THE RAKE,
RIPPING THE BOTTOM OFF IT,
STICK IT IN THE GROUND, AND THEN
YOU START STICKIN' MEAT ON HERE.
START WITH A BIG PIECE.
THIS LOOKS LIKE IT'S GONNA
BE A FAST PROCESS.
YOU HAVE TO GO LIKE THIS,
LIKE THIS, SO IT'S EVEN.
ORGANIZING IT SO WE HAVE
A GOOD MARBLING OF FAT
ALL THE WAY THROUGH IT.
HE'S MAKING A GIGANTIC
"TETRIS" OF MEAT.
JUST DOIN' LAMB AND BEEF
AND BEEF, BEEF, LAMB, LAMB
AND BEEF, LAMB, BEEF, BEEF,
BEEF, LAMB, BEEF, BEEF, BEEF.
LAMB, BEEF,
BEEF, BEEF.
LAMB-A-LAMB-A-LAMBY-
LAMBY-LAMBY..
BEEF, BEEF, BEEF.
YOU GOTTA GET
OUR NEW ALBUM.
WE HAVE "LAMB-A-LAMBA-
BEEF-BEEF."
OR "PORK
AND CHICKEN."
(laughs)
"PORK AND CHICKEN."
GET IT AT
YOUR GREEK WALMART.
OKAY, SO WE'RE CARVIN' IT
TO MAKE IT UNIFORM.
HE LOOK ALL THE TRIMMINGS
AND PUT 'EM RIGHT DOWN
AND THE BIG PIECES DRAPE OVER
IT, GONNA KIND OF HOUSE IT.
SO NOW WE GO
ALL THE WAY UP.
WE DO THE LAST TRIMMING.
WE PUT THIS FAT ON TOP
TO KEEP THE MEAT MOIST.
AND THEN WE PUT THE ONION.
THE JUICE OF THE ONION
GOES THROUGH THE MEAT
TO GIVE FLAVOR.
AND IT ALSO
LOOKS NICE.
OH, THAT'S GORGEOUS.
THERE SHOULD BE SLOW MUSIC,
LIKE "CHARIOTS OF FIRE."
♪♪
A THINK OF BEAUTY.
IT HAS AN ADJUSTER.
IT GOES IN AND OUT.
HOW CLOSE DO YOU WANT IT
TO BE TO THE FIRE?
YOU START IT OFF HIGH.
YOU WANT TO SEAR IT.
AND THE MEAT
DISCO BALL STARTS.
OKAY, IT'S BEEN ON
FOR 30 MINUTES.
WE GOTTA TURN THE FIRE
DOWN TO MEDIUM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SLOWLY START
TO COOK THE INSIDE.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU ONE.
OH, I LIKE THE WAY THAT'S GOIN'.
SO ANOTHER HALF AND HOUR?
LOOK AT THIS. CAN YOU SEE
THE JUICES BASTING EACH OTHER
AS IT GOES ALL THE WAY
TO THE BOTTOM?
THAT IS IT.
WE HAVE A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL AND OREGANO.
WE WARM UP THE PITA.
TAKE THE PITA OUT.
OKAY.
IT'S ALMOST READY.
YOU READY? LOOK HOW UNIFORM
THE LAYERS ARE.
LAMB, LAMB, BEEF, BEEF,
LAMB, LAMB...
BEEF, BEEF, LAMB,
LAMB, BEEF, BEEF.
SO WE'LL SPRINKLE
A LITTLE OREGANO AND SALT.
CRUNCHY. CARAMELIZED.
(grunts)
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GYRO.
(grunts)
OREGANO, TZATZIKI--
IT'S YOGURT...
CUCUMBERS, DILL, LEMON,
SALT AND PEPPER.
BEAUTIFUL.
TOMATOES, ONIONS, A LITTLE
PARSLEY AND A LITTLE LETTUCE.
AND NOW, READY.
MMM. YOU'VE NOT HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
THIS IS A REAL MEAT ATTACK.
THERE'S NICE CRUNCH.
THE MARINADE'S NOT OVERPOWERING.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY TASTE THE MEAT,
AND THERE'S JUICES
JUST RUNNIN'
OUT OF THIS THING.
THEN YOU PUT IT IN THIS WARM
PITA WITH THE ONIONS
AND THE TOMATO
AND THE TZATZIKI--
NOT OVERPOWERING ALSO--
THE CRUNCH AND THE MESS.
DUDE, 12-PACK AND REMOTE
CONTROL, MAN.
I WOULDN'T LEAVE HERE.
GYRO SANDWICH PICKUP.
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY FRESH.
(Themis) THAT'S
FOR HERE.
VERY WELL SEASONED.
IT'S REAL MEAT.
ON A REALLY FRESH
PITA BREAD.
GYRO SANDWICH.
IT'S LIKE BEING
IN GREECE AGAIN.
ARE YOU GREEK?
100%.
(Themis) SPINACH PIE.
(woman) I'M GREEK, AND, YES,
IT'S REALLY AUTHENTIC.
TARAMOSALATA.
'CAUSE THESE GUYS...
BAKED LAMB PICKUP.
ARE WORKIN'
FROM MOM'S COOKBOOK.
PASTITSO, PICK UP.
PASTITSO IS GREEK LASAGNA--
GROUND BEEF.
AND THE BéCHAMEL ON THE TOP--
IT'S PERFECT.
WHERE'S THE STOVE?
WE GOTTA COOK ON THE GRILL?
I COOK ON THE GRILL.
OKAY, YOU COOK ON THE GRILL.
WE START WITH
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
FROM ITALY?
FROM GREECE, BECAUSE WE
HAVE BETTER OIL.
ONIONS, FRESH GARLIC,
BAY LEAVES.
NOW WE ADD THE PEPPER.
CINNAMON STICKS.
THERE WE GO.
THEN CLOVES. WE LET IT
BROWN FOR TWO MINUTES.
NOW WE CAN ADD
THE MEAT.
SO BROWN ALL
THE MEAT UP?
BREAK IT APART. NOW WE'LL
CONTINUE WITH FRESH TOMATOES.
THAT'S ITALIAN, PROBABLY,
THE TOMATO.
(laughs)
TOMATO PASTE OR PURéE?
PURéE. WE STIR IT,
AND WE LEAVE IT UNTIL
COOKED TOGETHER WITH THE MEAT.
NOW WE'RE MAKING
BéCHAMEL SAUCE. MARGARINE.
THAT'S MARGARINE
ALL RIGHT.
MARGARINE IS MELTED.
GONNA ADD SOME FLOUR.
WHOSE RECIPE IS THIS?
MY MOM'S.
SHE LIVES IN GREECE.
SO WE GOT WARM MILK
SO IT'LL MAKE
THE BéCHAMEL A LOT EASIER.
YOU START THICKENING IT UP.
COOKED A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT FLOUR TASTE OUT.
NOW WE ADD EGGS.
DON'T WANT TO
DO 'EM TOO FAST.
DON'T WANT AN OMELET.
ALL RIGHT.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
TELL ME WHEN.
PERFECT. NUTMEG.
MORE. MORE.
THEN BLACK PEPPER?
LITTLE BLACK PEPPER, AND THEN
SOME GRATED PARMESAN CHEESE.
STIFFENIN' UP.
YEP, WE'RE GONNA START
BUILDING THE PASTITSO.
MELTED MARGARINE--ITALY.
THAT'S FROM ITALY.
WE ADD THREE MORE EGGS AND THEN
SOME MORE PARMESAN CHEESE.
NOW THE MILK?
NOW THE MILK.
THEN WE ADD THE MEAT.
HOW DOES IT LOOK?
LOOKS LIKE I WANT TO EAT IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE BéCHAMEL.
THAT'S A LOT OF CREAMY
GOODNESS RIGHT THERE, HUH?
A LITTLE BIT MORE PARMESAN
CHEESE ON THE TOP.
OKAY, NOW WE TAKE IT, PUT IT
IN THE OVEN 45 MINUTES,
300 DEGREES.
45 MINUTES, 300 DEGREES.
IT'S READY.
SLICE IT UP.
YOU WANT A CORNER?
I'M FANS OF THE CORNER.
I LIKE THAT ONE RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S CLASSIC PASTITSO.
YOU GET THE CLOVE, CINNAMON.
IT ALL COMES THROUGH.
REAL INTENSE GREEK.
PASTA'S STILL AL DENTE.
LOOK AT HOW CREAMY THAT IS.
LITTLE BIT OF EGG
HELPED TO TIGHTEN IT UP.
CAN'T GET TIRED
OF HAVIN' PASTITSO.
IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
THIS IS GREEK 101
RIGHT HERE. NICE JOB, BUDDY.
THANK YOU.
PASTITSO.
VERY GOOD.
IT'S GREEK COMFORT FOOD.
COOKED PERFECTLY.
NICE AND MOIST.
JUST LIKE YAYA'S.
IS THAT GRANDMOTHER?
IT'S GRANDMOTHER
IN GREEK.
PASTITSO, PLEASE.
EVERYTHING IS VERY FLAVORFUL.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
FALAFEL PLATE.
VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
GYRO SANDWICH.
(Guy) THE GYRO'S ONE OF THE BEST
I'VE HAD IN MY LIFE.
AWESOME. AWESOME JOB.
THANK YOU.
LET ME PUT MY GLASSES
THIS WAY.
JUST LIKE THAT. SEE?
OH, OKAY.
LET ME SEE. SEE?
YOU GOTTA COME MEET THESE GUYS.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE 'EM.
UP NEXT...
AND 1 POUND OF CRAWFISH
FOR YOU.
WE'RE HEADED TO NASHVILLE...
VERY AUTHENTIC.
AND DOWN ON THE BAYOU.
THESE NASHVILLE FOLKS KNOW HOW
TO HANDLE GOOD CAJUN LIKE YOU?
THEY LEARN.
NOW THAT RIGHT THERE
IS I440.
AND ON THE OTHER SIDE OF IT--
YOU CAN ALMOST SEE IT--
IS CENTENNIAL PARK,
AND I'M HERE ON THE WEST SIDE
OF NASHVILLE
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE THE LOUISIANA CHEF
STARTED COOKIN' AS A KID,
GOT SERIOUS ABOUT IT
IN THE NAVY,
THEN MADE IT HIS CAREER WITHOUT
FORGETTIN' HIS CAJUN ROOTS.
THIS IS BRO'S CAJUN CUISINE.
SHRIMP CREOLE,
TABLE TEN.
THE FOOD IS JUST
OUTRAGEOUS.
LET'S GO.
THESE PEOPLE ARE HUNGRY.
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE, YOU
DON'T NORMALLY THINK OF CAJUN.
AND 1 POUND OF CRAWFISH.
IT'S ALL VERY AUTHENTIC.
DARRELL IS A REAL CAJUN.
YOU SEE IT BY THE ACCENT.
THAT'D BE OWNER DARRELL BREAUX
THESE NASHVILLE FOLKS KNOW HOW
TO HANDLE A GOOD CAJUN LIKE YOU?
THEY LEARN.
WHO MOVED TO NASHVILLE
MORE THAN 22 YEARS AGO...
HOW MANY POUNDS OF CRAWFISH
CAME IN TODAY?
AND KEPT ON COOKIN'
LIKE HE DID BACK HOME.
(Darrell) GOT
SOME FRESH CATFISH.
IT'S JUST GOOD
DOWN-HOME FOOD.
HE MAKES EVERYTHING.
YEP, EVERYTHING.
WE'RE MAKIN' SAUSAGE
WITH PORK BUTT.
WHAT WE DO,
WE CUBE 'EM UP,
AND THEN WE JUST DUMP IT IN
THE OLD GRINDER HERE.
OKAY. WHAT ARE
YOU HITTIN' IT WITH?
SALT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
CAYENNE PEPPER.
(whistles) A LITTLE ICE?
THE MACHINE...
GETS HOT?
RIGHT. EXACTLY.
I LIKE IT
COMIN' OUT PREMIXED.
A GIGANTIC PLAY-DOH
MACHINE IN FLAVOR TOWN.
DUMP IT BACK IN.
MIX IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
RUN IT AGAIN,
BUT THIS TIME, WE'RE GONNA
PUT ON THE ATTACHMENT.
NOW WE'RE READY
FOR OUR CASING.
YOU START THREADING ON
A BUNCH OF THAT CASING.
READY?
HIT IT. A LITTLE BIT OF AIR
OUT. GOTTA CONTROL THE TEMPO.
YOU JUST HOLD ON, BOSS.
I GOT IT.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
FRESH SAUSAGE, CAJUN STYLE.
WE HANG IT OVERNIGHT IN
THE COOLER, THEN THE NEXT DAY,
IT'LL BE READY FOR
THE FOR THE SMOKEHOUSE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SMOKE 'EM WITH?
HICKORY. 7 1/2, 8 HOURS.
WE READY?
SMOKED SAUSAGE?
YES, SIR.
THERE WE GO.
ISN'T THAT PRETTY?
I THINK THIS IS
ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WHERE THEY LOCK ME IN THERE
AND SEE HOW MUCH I CAN EAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, MAN.
A LITTLE SNAP TO THAT CASING
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
THAT COMES OUT OF THAT.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
AND DARRELL'S SERVIN' IT UP
ALL OVER THE MENU...
GUMBO, PICK UP.
FROM GUMBO...
THE GUMBO IS MY FAVORITE.
TO RED BEANS AND RICE...
YOU CAN'T GET IT BETTER
IN NEW ORLEANS. REALLY.
AND THIS CAJUN CLASSIC.
CRAWFISH BOIL
FOR TABLE TEN.
HE REALLY KNOWS HOW TO
COOK 'EM. THEY'RE PERFECT.
WE'RE READY TO BOIL
SOME CRAWFISH,
AND WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS CLEAN 'EM.
WASH 'EM OFF.
WE'RE USING COLD WATER.
SOME SALT
IN MY MIDDLE CONTAINER.
TAKE MY OL' FAITHFUL
STRAINER.
I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST
AN UNLUCKY HELMET.
PUSH THAT SALT AROUND.
HOW LONG THEY GONNA SIT
IN THAT SALT WATER?
ABOUT 10, 15 MINUTES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA RINSE 'EM,
AND THEN WE GO TO THE POT.
YES, SIR.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SEASONED
WATER FOR THE CRAWFISH.
WHEN YOU'RE USING THIS
KIND OF KETTLE,
THIS IS GETTIN' IT GOING.
YES, SIR. STEAM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN WE WANT TO THROW IN
OUR CRAB AND CRAWFISH BOIL.
THAT'S WHAT I USE.
CHINESE RED PEPPER.
THAT SWEETENS.
THAT'S GOT SOME HEAT TO IT?
OH, THAT JUST SWEETENS IT.
(laughs) YEAH.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
LEMON JUICE.
LIQUID CRAB BOIL.
ANOTHER ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
SALT AND CAYENNE
FOR THE FLAVOR.
OH, YEAH,
CHOPPED-UP LEMONS, ONIONS,
MORE WATER, STIR IT UP.
OOH, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
LET IT SIMMER
A LITTLE WHILE
SO ALL YOUR SEASONS
CAN BLEND TOGETHER.
KIND OF MARRY
TOGETHER. RIGHT.
30 MINUTES BEFORE WE CAN
HIT IT WITH SOME CRAWFISH?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT. THERE WE GO.
WOW.
BYE-BYE.
BYE-BYE. HOW LONG
ARE THESE GONNA RUN FOR?
15 TO 20 MINUTES.
THEN MY POTATOES.
I LIKE IT.
SMOKED SAUSAGES
AND CORN ON THE COB.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THEN CLOSE THE LID ON IT.
TURN THE HEAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
15, 20 MINUTES,
IT'LL BE GOOD TO GO.
NOW THERE WE GO.
ISN'T THAT NICE?
I WONDERED WHERE
MY POOL SCOOP WENT.
THIS IS WHERE THEY'RE JUST GONNA
HANG OUT SO THEY STAY WARM?
A LITTLE KISS OF THAT SPICE.
STIR IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
WHEN WE GONNA EAT IT?
WHENEVER YOU READY.
I STAY READY.
"WHENEVER YOU READY.
I STAY READY."
(laughs)
SO THAT'S HOW
IT COMES OUT TO YOU?
MMM, WOW.
THAT IS AN EXPERIENCE.
LOOK AT THAT TENDER LITTLE TAIL
AND A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
MMM. I CAN'T GET IT IN
FAST ENOUGH.
I'VE HAD GREAT CRAWFISH
DOWN IN LOUISIANA.
A GOOD BUDDY OF MINE,
KIM GARDNER.
I THINK OLD KIM WOULD BE
IMPRESSED WITH THIS ONE. MMM.
THAT IS A GREAT BOIL.
(woman) 1 POUND
OF CRAWFISH.
THEY'RE JUST FABULOUS.
THEY KNOW WHAT THEY'RE DOIN'
WITH CRAWFISH.
GOT A CRAWFISH BOIL
TO TABLE EIGHT.
I AM FROM LOUISIANA.
THIS IS LIKE GOIN' TO
GRANDMA'S HOUSE AND EATIN'.
I TRY TO COOK, LIKE,
THE WAY MY MOTHER
TAUGHT ME HOW.
BUT HE LEARNED THIS ONE
FROM HIS DAD...
GET ME A PORK CHOP READY
FOR THIS ORDER.
AT THE BUTCHER COUNTER
OF THE FAMILY GROCERY STORE
BACK IN LOUISIANA.
(man) THE STUFFED PORK CHOP,
IT'S SOMETHING YOU HAVE TO TRY.
I MEAN, IT'S JUST REALLY GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF WITH
A LITTLE BARBECUE SAUCE.
BUTTER, OLIVE OIL.
I LIKE YOUR MEASURING STYLE.
CHOPPED ONIONS, THEN WE SAUTé
THE ONIONS A LITTLE BIT.
KETCHUP, TOMATO JUICE.
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR.
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME MAPLE SYRUP.
MAPLE SYRUP.
MAKE IT GOOD AND SWEET.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
MOLASSES?
"SHOOSTER" SAUCE.
WORCESTERSHIRE-SH-SH-SHIRE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THIS MANY INGREDIENTS
IN ONCE BARBECUE SAUCE.
CHILI POWDER, VINEGAR,
GARLIC POWDER,
CELERY SEED, LEMON JUICE.
THEN SOME CORN NUTS
IN A MINUTE.
BLACK PEPPER, RED PEPPER,
SALT, BEEF BASE,
WATER, STIR IT UP.
HOW LONG'S THIS
GONNA SIMMER?
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
GONNA PUT ON THOSE CHOPS?
YES, SIR. ALL RIGHT,
LET'S COOK SOME PORK LOIN.
WET MY SAW A LITTLE BIT.
THAT WAY,
THE MEAT'LL SLIDE EASY.
HE'S CUTTING
THE PORK CHOP!
AN INCH AND A HALF THICK.
THAT'S IT.
SO WE'LL TAKE THESE, AND THIS
IS THE GROUND PORK BUTT.
COARSE GRIND.
CORRECT.
AND WE'RE GONNA STUFF IT
INSIDE THE CHOPS.
EXACTLY.
START OFF WITH YOUR SALT,
GARLIC, RED PEPPER.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA.
GIVE IT A CAJUN SMILE
WITH THE GREEN ONIONS.
WHAT'D YOU CALL THAT?
A CAJUN SMILE?
YEAH, MAKE YOU SMILE
WHEN YOU EAT IT.
WATER TO MIX IT UP EASIER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
STUFFIN' THOSE CHOPS.
WE'RE GONNA CLEAN 'EM UP.
LOOK ALL PRETTY.
CUT A LITTLE POCKET IN HERE.
PUT IT INTO THE SAUSAGE STUFFER.
OKAY.
WHAT THE MACHINE DOES
IS PACKS IT IN THERE.
PRESSURIZES IT.
WHOA.
RIGHT. THERE SHE IS.
(whistles) LOOK AT THOSE.
NOW WE GOTTA SEASON IT.
WHAT'S IN THAT SEASONING,
BOSS?
SALT, GRANULATED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, CHILI POWDER
AND RED PEPPER.
SEASON 'EM AND PUT 'EM
IN THE WALK-IN.
CORRECT.
24 HOURS. SO THEY'LL
GO ON THE BIG BARBECUE.
AFTER 30 MINUTES,
WE'LL TURN 'EM,
AND THEN ANOTHER 15 MINUTES,
WE'LL START BASTING THEM.
MY GOOD OLD BARBECUE SAUCE.
GONNA LET IT GRILL A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN LET 'EM GO
ABOUT ANOTHER 15 MINUTES?
YEP, TURN 'EM OVER
AND BASTE 'EM AGAIN.
THEY'LL BE READY TO GO.
OH, MAN, ISN'T THAT NICE?
NICE.
THERE WE GO.
CAJUN-STYLE PORK CHOP.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, OH, THAT'S GOOD EATS.
NICE TENDER-COOKED
PORK CHOP
WITH THE GLAZE THAT WE MADE
STUFFED WITH SAUSAGE.
THAT'S FLAVOR INSIDE AND OUT.
YOU GOTTA COME TRY SOME OF THAT.
(woman) A PORK CHOP
FOR YOU.
TWO FLAVORS IN ONE.
THAT'S OFF THE CHAIN.
OF THE CHAIN.
OFF THE CHAIN.
IT'S THAT GOOD.
I'VE GOT A GUMBO
AND A BOUDIN READY TO PICK UP.
BEST PLACE
YOU COULD FIND.
I GOT A RIB EYE STEAK
PO' BOY READY.
IT IS TRUE CAJUN FOOD.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
WE HAVE HAD A BLAST.
JUST CHECKIN' OUT THE SMOKER,
SITTIN' ON A BELLYFUL OF FOOD.
I MEAN, WHAT A PLEASURE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
REALLY ENJOYED IT.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP...
FRIED CHICKEN
WITH MAC AND CHEESE.
WE'RE HEADED OUTSIDE OF D.C...
THE FOOD'S INCREDIBLE.
FOR TRUE
AMERICAN CLASSICS.
(woman) TURKEY TURNOVERS.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
YOU KNOW, I LOVE SHOOTIN'
ON THE EAST COAST.
WITH ALL THE HISTORY
AND NOSTALGIA,
IT MAKES EACH LOCATION
REALLY UNIQUE.
SO HERE I AM
IN SILVER SPRING, MARYLAND,
JUST OUTSIDE OF D.C.,
TO VISIT A JOINT
THAT SAYS THEY'RE CELEBRATING
THE AMERICAN CLASSICS.
AND THEY'RE DOIN' IT--
GET THIS--IN A BUILDING
FROM 1883 THAT USED TO BE
THE GENERAL STORE
AND POST OFFICE.
I GUESS IT'S ONLY FITTING THEY
CALL IT THE GENERAL STORE.
CHICKEN POTPIE.
ENJOY.
THE FOOD'S INCREDIBLE.
THERE YOU GO.
THE MACARONI AND CHEESE
IS FANTASTIC.
FRIED CHICKEN.
BEST FRIED CHICKEN
YOU EVER HAD.
ALL CRANKED OUT BY OWNERS
GILLIAN CLARK...
I'M BRINGING THEM OUT
RIGHT NOW.
AND ROBIN SMITH.
OKAY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
AREN'T USED TO FOOD
REALLY COMING FROM SCRATCH.
WE'RE GETTING PEOPLE TO GET BACK
IN TOUCH WITH AMERICAN FOOD.
LIKE COLLARD GREENS, CORNBREAD,
AND THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC.
FRIED CHICKEN--
IT'S, LIKE, GREAT.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE MAKING FRIED CHICKEN.
START WITH THE MARINADE.
BUTTERMILK.
I ADD HOT SAUCE,
CRUSHED GARLIC,
IT HASN'T BEEN CHOPPED.
THIS IS JUST GONNA GIVE
AN OVERTONE OF GARLIC,
BUT NOT AN OVERWHELMING--
THIS ISN'T
GARLIC-HOT-SAUCE CHICKEN.
NO.
I'VE GOT MY PIECES OF CHICKEN,
BUT IT'S MARINATED 24 HOURS.
GIVE IT TO ME.
THEN WHEN WE COME BACK,
WHAT'S THE DREDGE
GONNA BE?
FLOUR, GOOD AMOUNT
OF SALT,
FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
SO I'LL COAT IT REALLY WELL.
YOU GIVE 'EM A LITTLE BIT
OF A SHAKE,
BUT YOU'RE NOT GONNA NECESSARILY
KNOCK EVERYTHING OFF.
MNH-MNH.
WHEN YOU'RE GONNA GET SERIOUS
ABOUT FRIED CHICKEN,
LOOK AT THIS.
IT ALSO WORKS AS A GOOD
LITTLE MINI HOT TUB
FOR THE KIDS.
I'M GONNA ADD CORN OIL.
HALF A POUND OF BUTTER.
REALLY?
THAT'S WHAT MAKES
THAT CRUST SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE A PIECE OF BREAD
WITH BUTTER ON IT.
WE FEEL GOOD
ABOUT THE TEMP?
ONE OF THE NUMBER-ONE-
SELLING ITEMS?
WHEN WE RUN OUT,
THERE'S REALLY HELL TO PAY.
REALLY?
YEAH. IT TAKES EIGHT
TO TEN MINUTES
FOR THAT CRUST TO GET
REALLY, REALLY GOOD AND BROWN.
IT TAKES ANOTHER, LIKE,
FIVE TO TEN MINUTES
ON THE OTHER SIDE,
AND THEN WE GO INTO THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
WITH THE FRIED CHICKEN,
WE MAKE CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
MM-HMM.
AND INSTEAD OF
JUST MAPLE SYRUP,
I MAKE A CHICKEN GRAVY
MAPLE SYRUP.
CHICKEN GRAVY
AND MAPLE SYRUP?
WE CALL IT
CHICKEN MAPLE SYRUP.
SO WE START WITH
CHICKEN STOCK, BROWN SUGAR.
CHICKEN STOCK
WITH BROWN SUGAR.
THAT IS THE ODDEST THING
I THINK I'VE SEEN.
YOU GOTTA COME ON DOWN FOR OUR
CARMEL CANDY MEATBALLS
THAT WE'LL BE DOING LATER.
BUTTER AND FLOUR.
THIS IS YOUR ROUX.
AND THEN YOU'RE JUST
GONNA SLOWLY DAB THAT IN.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
THE SYRUP.
OF COURSE.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
SO DO WE TRY IT?
THAT WORKS.
NOW IT'S TIME
TO MAKE WAFFLES.
MAKE OUR WAFFLES
FROM SCRATCH.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW WE'VE
GOT THE FRIED CHICKEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND OUR WAFFLE'S READY.
THERE WE HAVE IT.
LIKE THAT ONE
AND THAT ONE.
AND WE HAVE OUR GRAVY.
THAT'S PRETTY NUTS.
NOW LET ME SHOW YOU THIS.
OH, LOOK AT THAT CHICKEN.
ROLL THIS UP.
MMM, GET OUTTA HERE
WITH THAT GRAVY.
(chuckles)
THE CHICKEN IS COOKED
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
THE SALTY CRUNCH
OF THE BREADING
JUST HOLDS ON REALLY NICE.
MMM.
THE AMOUNT OF HOT SAUCE
YOU PUT IN THAT OWNS IT.
WAFFLE'S LIKE A BIG,
CRUNCHY FLOUR TORTILLA.
(laughs)
(woman) CHICKEN
AND WAFFLES.
YOU GOT THE SWEET.
YOU GOT THE SALTY.
OUT OF THIS WORLD.
MMM.
THIS IS IS ABOUT READY.
SHE HAS SUCH
AN ATTENTION TO DETAIL.
THERE YOU GO.
WE'RE 100% SCRATCH KITCHEN.
(woman) IT'S COMIN'.
EVERYTHING.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
CHICKEN TARRAGON.
SHE'S MAKING WHAT APPEAR
TO BE SIMPLE FOODS.
THE WAY SHE DOES IT,
IT'S SOMETHING SPECIAL.
LIKE A CRISPY SHRIMP SANDWICH.
MMM. IT'S GREAT.
OR A MADE-TO-ORDER
CHEESESTEAK.
(man) THIS ISN'T
THE KIND OF THING
YOU GET FROM YOUR AVERAGE
SANDWICH SHOP.
AND NEITHER ARE THESE.
TURKEY AND BRIE TURNOVER.
VERY GOOD.
TURKEY AND BRIE
TURNOVERS.
TURKEY AND WHAT?
BRIE... ORANGE GLAZE.
IN A TURNOVER?
WE'RE GONNA ROAST A TURKEY,
AND WE'LL START
WITH THE MIREPOIX IN
THE PAN--ONIONS, CARROTS,
CELERY.
A LITTLE FRESH THYME.
A LITTLE 15-POUND BIRD.
IN THE OVEN.
AT ABOUT 350,
375 FOR TWO HOURS.
ENOUGH, OKAY?
I USE THE BREAST
AND THE THIGH,
A LITTLE BIT OF SKIN
REAL FINE IN THERE.
SO THIS IS HOW WE MAKE
THE FILLING
FOR THE TURKEY TURNOVERS.
BUTTER.
AND SOME SHALLOTS.
A LITTLE THYME.
LET THAT WILT.
WE ADD SOME WHITE WINE,
CHICKEN STOCK.
WHICH YOU MAKE YOURSELF.
I DON'T MAKE THIS.
HEAVY CREAM.
BUT YOU DO
MILK THE COW.
IT'S ON THE ROOF.
AND SOME TURKEY MEAT.
SO THIS'LL COOK DOWN?
COOL IT. SALT. PEPPER.
NOW IT'S GONNA BE
THE STUFFING.
I HAVE A SQUARE
OF PUFF PASTRY.
ADD THAT IN.
A SLICE OF THE BRIE.
AND I HAVE EGG WASH.
THIS IS MY GLUE.
AND THEN I'M GONNA JUST
FORK THE EDGES DOWN.
THOSE ARE KNOCKED OUT.
WE JUST BRUSH THEM
WITH EGG WASH,
SO THAT THEY HAVE A NICE,
GOLDEN COLOR WHEN THEY--
POKE A LITTLE HOLE
IN THERE, TOO,
SO THEY DON'T
STEAM UP ON US?
YEAH. THERE WE GO.
350.
FOR ABOUT...
20 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GLAZE?
THE SALTY ORANGE GLAZE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING
WE WOULD PUT ON LIKE A DESSERT.
ORANGE ZEST,
ORANGE JUICE,
POWDERED SUGAR, SALT,
AND THAT'S OUR GLAZE.
READY TO DRESS
OUR TURNOVERS.
WOW, LOOK AT HOW THAT
JUST PUFFED.
AND WE GLAZE IT.
THERE WE GO.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
MMM. IT'S OUTSTANDING.
IF THERE AS NOTHING IN THERE...
YOU HAD ME AT "GLAZE."
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
THE TURKEY IN THERE
WITH THAT CREAMINESS
OF THE BRIE.
THIS IS THE KIND
OF TURNOVER I WANT.
JUST A TOUCH OF THE SUGAR
AND TOUCH OF THE SALT
WITH THE ORANGE--
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
MMM, THAT'S AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVOR.
TURKEY TURNOVERS.
THE CRUST IS NICE
AND FLAKY. DELICIOUS.
(woman) A LOT OF THE FOOD THEY
SERVE, YOU EAT WITH YOUR HANDS.
IT'S JUST FUN.
(woman) CORN DOG.
(Guy) YOU THINK?
IT'S A BIG OLD SLICE
OF AMERICANA.
SO WHEN WE COME BACK,
I'M GONNA BITE
INTO THE THERMONUCLEAR DOG
HERE AT THE GENERAL STORE.
OKAY, CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
IN SLIVER SPRING, MARYLAND...
HAM TURNOVER.
THE GENERAL STORE OWNERS,
GILLIAN CLARK...
TWO ORDERS OF TURKEY TURNOVERS.
AND ROBIN SMITH...
WANT TO RUN THIS OUT?
ARE COOKIN'
LIKE THE OLD DAYS
IN A BUILDING
FROM THE 19th CENTURY...
IT DOES FEEL LIKE
A LITTLE STEP BACK IN TIME.
DOIN' THEIR TAKE
ON THE CLASSICS OF EVERY KIND.
(woman) CORN DOG.
AND NOT JUST ANY CORN DOG.
WAGYU BEEF HOT DOG.
AMERICAN KOBE.
NICE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN' NOW?
WE'RE MAKING CORN DOGS.
OKAY.
VERY UNIQUE COMPILATION
OF MENU ITEMS
YOU HAVE HERE.
(laughs)
IT'S A BIG OLD SLICE
OF AMERICANA.
YEAH, IT IS.
ON A STICK.
CHOP STICKS WORK
REALLY WELL.
JUST THE RIGHT TENSILE
STRENGTH. IT'S A QUARTER POUND.
SERIOUSLY?
MM-HMM. START WITH
THREE BEATEN EGGS.
IT'S LIKE A PANCAKE BATTER.
AND THEN SOME MILK.
NOW SOME CORNMEAL.
WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR.
GIVES A CRISPNESS TO IT
AND A SNAP, AND THEN
REGULAR ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
BAKING SODA...
A LITTLE LEAVENING.
SOME SALT, SUGAR.
IT HELPS IT GET THIS
NICE GOLDEN COLOR.
THE CARAMELIZATION
OF THE SUGAR.
MM-HMM.
WELL, YOU GOT THAT
GOIN' ON RIGHT THERE.
THEN WE PUT THE BATTER
IN A MASON JAR.
I LIKE IT.
AND IT'S EASIER TO COAT
THAT HOT DOG
IN SOMETHING TALL
AND SKINNY.
JUST SWIRL IT UP--
A LITTLE BIT UP ON--
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE READY TO FRY.
OIL AT WHAT TEMP?
350.
HOLD IT UP A LITTLE BIT
LIKE THAT
SO IT DOESN'T STICK
TO THE BOTTOM.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE WITH IT?
HONEY MUSTARD
THAT I MAKE WITH--
OF COURSE YOU MAKE IT.
PROBABLY TRAINED THE BEES
TO EAT MUSTARD.
THAT'S HOW WE MAKE IT.
IT'S, YOU KNOW, THEY DON'T
SPARE ANY EXPENSE HERE.
WHOA, JUST LIKE
AT THE FAIR.
ONLY BIGGER.
(whistles) THIS IS
JUST THE TEMPERATURE
OF THE SURFACE OF THE SUN.
I MEAN, EVEN THE CHOPSTICK
IS HOT.
IT'S HOT.
READY FOR THAT ONE?
WHAT'D YOU GUYS SAY?
YOU WANT HER TO TRY IT FIRST?
(laughs)
OKAY, TIME TO GO.
MMM, OH, MY GOSH,
THAT IS GOOD.
WOW, LOOK A THAT.
YOU BITE INTO IT, AND IT JUST
GIVES THIS EXTRA TEXTURE.
IT'S NOT JUST A CORN MUFFIN
WRAPPED AROUND A HOT DOG.
THERE'S TEXTURE TO IT. A LITTLE
BIT OF SWEETNESS. PREMIUM DOG.
I MEAN, THAT MAKES ALL
THE DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD.
MMM, IF YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A CORN DOG,
THIS IS THE KIND OF CORN DOG
TO GO AFTER.
MM-HMM.
WAY TO KICK IT DOWN.
(woman) THERE'S
YOUR CORN DOG.
(man) A LITTLE BIT
OF SALTINESS IN THE DOG.
IT ACCENTUATES THE SWEETNESS
OF THE CORNBREAD.
REALLY FANTASTIC.
(woman) THEY PUT SOME
LOVE INTO THIS FOOD.
CAN I GET AN EXTRA SIDE
OF LOVE?
IT'S ALWAYS IN THERE.
I'M WORKING ON THE POTPIE.
(man) IT'S A MEMORABLE
EXPERIENCE EVERY TIME
THAT YOU COME INTO HERE.
MACARONI AND CHEESE.
(Guy) YOU'VE GOT
AN ECLECTIC MIX OF FOOD,
AND YOU DO IT ALL
FROM SCRATCH.
I MEAN, YOU'RE DOIN' IT THE REAL
DEAL, SO CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
WOW, WAS THAT
A ROAD TRIP OR WHAT?
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE PLACES
TO FIND ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN'
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
BEEF, BEEFY-BEEF,
LAMB, LAMB, BEEF.
A-BEEF, A-BEEF, A-BEEF,
BEEF, BEEF, BEEF.
LAMB, LAMB,
LAMB, LAMB, BEEF.
LAMB, BEEF.
WHAT'D YOU THINK
OF THAT ONE?