HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
SMELL THAT.
FRESH...
WHOA.
FILLED...
(woman) STUFFED PORK CHOP.
AND FRIED.
WHERE'S THAT BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
IN PHILADELPHIA...
HI, FOLKS.
HOW YOU DOING TONIGHT?
THE LOCAL PUB...
GOOD FOOD. GOOD BEER.
DOIN' DUCK POT PIE...
HOT, CREAMY, IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND DEEP-FRYIN' THEIR TAKE...
TRUFFLED CHEESESTEAK
EMPANADAS.
ON A PHILADELPHIA CLASSIC.
OH.
DELICIOUS. THAT RIGHT THERE IS
A WORLD-CLASS EMPANADA.
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
IT'S JUST LIKE NOTHING ELSE.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
GOOD MORNING.
STUFFIN' CHOPS...
MMM.
AND BAKIN' BERRIES...
OH!
INTO THE FRENCH TOAST.
WOW. LOOK AT THAT.
AND IN PORTLAND, MAINE...
LOBSTER SANDWICH.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
THE WATERFRONT LANDMARK...
RIGHT ON THE PIER.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN BRINGIN' IN
FRESH SEAFOOD...
CAN'T GET ANY FRESHER THAN THIS.
FOR MORE THAN 80 YEARS.
FRIED GINGER SQUID.
TO FIND CALAMARI
THAT IS THAT FRESH--
GREAT JOB, MAN.
WAY TO DO IT.
THANKS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN CENTER CITY PHILADELPHIA.
NOW I DON'T KNOW IF YOU HAVE
EVER BEEN DOWN HERE
DURING THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY,
BUT PARKING'S A LITTLE TOUGH,
SO THE CAMARO'S
AROUND THE CORNER.
I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
A JOINT THAT'S IN A BUILDING
THAT'S OVER 100 YEARS OLD,
AND IT'S BEEN A BAR, GET THIS,
SINCE PROHIBITION.
I HEAR THEY HAVE
SOME MEAN LIBATIONS,
AND THE FOOD'S ON POINT.
THIS IS GOOD DOG.
GOOD DOG BURGER MEDIUM
IN THE WINDOW.
IT DOES LOOK LIKE A DIVE BAR.
CHEESESTEAK EMPANADAS.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
CHICKEN TENDERS
CORDON BLEU.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
I LOVE THE DOGS.
NOT HOT DOGS.
ALL THE PICTURES OF THE DOGS
ON THE WALL...
'CAUSE OWNER HEATHER GLEASON...
HI, FOLKS, HOW YOU
DOIN' TONIGHT?
LOVES DOGS AS MUCH AS SHE LOVES
RUNNING THIS JOINT.
NOTHING GOES ON THIS MENU
BEFORE I TASTE IT.
QUESADILLA.
ALMOST EVERYTHING'S
SCRATCH-MADE?
YES.
BY CHEF JESSICA O'DONNELL.
FRIES, THREE TIMES.
I CALL IT UPSCALE
COMFORT FOOD.
LIKE MAC AND CHEESE
WITH GRUYèRE...
IT TASTES SO GOOD.
STUFFED BURGERS
ON BRIOCHE...
GET THE BURGER.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
OR, OH, YEAH, JUST YOUR
BASIC POT PIE.
IT'S DUCK CONFIT IN THE POT PIE.
HOT, CREAMY--IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING
FIRST?
DUCK CONFIT POT PIE.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A DUCK STOCK?
YES, SIR.
I HAVE MY RAW DUCK BONES.
IN THE OVEN,
ABOUT AN HOUR
UNTIL THEY'RE BROWN.
PULL 'EM OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS THE WAY TO DO IT.
ANY GREAT STOCK--
IT COMES FROM
THE BONE.
PUT 'EM IN OUR POT.
NEXT THING IS THE MIREPOIX--
CELERY, CARROTS AND ONIONS,
PARSLEY STEMS.
LOT OF FLAVOR.
FRESH THYME,
PEPPERCORNS, STAR ANISE.
STAR ANISE.
CINNAMON STICK, ALLSPICE,
AND WATER.
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
REDUCE IT TO A SIMMER,
IGNORE IT FOR FIVE HOURS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT,
STRAIN IT A SECOND TIME
THROUGH A FINER STRAINER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HAVE
DUCK STOCK.
YOU GOT IT. BRING IT BACK UP
TO A BOIL IN A DIFFERENT POT,
SEASON WITH SOME SALT.
NOW WE CAN BLANCH
THE VEGETABLES FOR THE POT PIE.
FIRST THE ONIONS.
BLANCH IN THE DUCK STOCK.
IN THE DUCK STOCK.
(whistles)
NEXT THE CELERY,
POTATOES AND CARROTS.
BIG PROCESS
FOR ONE POT PIE.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA
MAKE OUR ROUX.
BUTTER, ADD MY FLOUR,
WHISK THIS.
POUR THE DUCK STOCK INTO
THE ROUX A LITTLE BIT AT A TIME.
REALLY MAKE SURE THAT YOU
INCORPORATE IT ALL IN,
OR WE GET DUMPLINGS.
THERE WE GO.
JUST GONNA COOK
THAT FLOUR OUT.
BRING IT TO A BOIL AGAIN,
LET IT REDUCE,
SO WE GET THE PROPER
CONSISTENCY FOR OUR GRAVY.
CHECK THE BACK OF THE SPOON.
LOOK AT THAT.
PERFECT. TASTE IT.
TASTES GREAT. NICE,
SUBTLE DUCK FLAVOR,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA START
SEASONING.
YOU GOT IT.
QUITE A BIT OF SALT.
FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF FIVE SPICE.
CHINESE FIVE SPICE.
YES, SIR. IN OUR BLEND,
WE HAVE CINNAMON, CORIANDER,
CLOVES, GINGER
AND NUTMEG.
INTERESTING.
TASTE IT AGAIN, SEE WHERE
WE'RE AT. I WANT MORE SALT.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
FIVE SPICE IS FANTASTIC.
WE'VE GOT THIS READY.
NEXT STEP IS TO ADD ALL OF OUR
ACTUAL POT PIE INGREDIENTS.
SHREDDED DUCK CONFIT,
SHIITAKE MUSHROOM
ROASTED WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF FRESH THYME,
OLIVE OIL, SALT, PEPPER,
BLANCHED POTATO,
CARROTS, CELERY, ONIONS...
I LIKE THIS RATIO.
AND SOME PEAS.
STIR THAT ALL UP.
YOU GOTTA SEE THIS.
WANT TO TASTE
ONE MORE TIME.
IF THE CRUST IS HALF
AS GOOD AS THAT IS,
IT'S GONNA BE A WINNER,
WINNER, DUCK PIE DINNER.
WE'RE ROLLING OUT
POT PIE DOUGH.
YOU MAKE THIS EVERY DAY?
UH-HUH.
CRAZY.
ROLL IT OUT.
LAY THAT RIGHT IN THERE, ROLL
OUT ANOTHER ONE FOR THE TOP.
YOU'RE GONNA FILL IT UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
MAY EAT IT THAT WAY.
TOP CRUST ON,
TRIM THE EDGES.
MAKE IT PRETTY.
FOLD THE EDGES UNDER
AND SEAL THEM DOWN WITH A FORK.
SCORE THE TOP SO IT DOESN'T
BUBBLE ON YOU.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF EGG WHITE WASH.
BROWNS THE EDGES
AND BROWNS THE TOP NICE.
THAT'S IT.
SO YOU THROW IT
IN THE OVEN.
ABOUT 20 MINUTES,
GOLDEN BROWN.
OKAY, LET'S ROLL. MMM.
GET OUTTA HERE.
THAT'S REMARKABLE.
THAT'S GOT SOME REAL
DEPTH AND SOME GREAT FLAVOR.
ALL THE ESSENCE
OF DUCK CONFIT. MMM.
THE RICHNESS, BUT THEN YOU GET
THAT LITTLE TOUCH OF FIVE SPICE.
NICE LITTLE SNAP OUT OF
THE PEAS. THE CRUST IS ON POINT,
AND THAT'S FOUR BITES, AND I
HAVEN'T EVEN MADE A DENT IN IT.
THIS IS OFF THE HOOK.
PRIME TIME.
DUCK POT PIE.
ALWAYS FLAKY AND CRISPY.
IT'S VERY RICH IN FLAVORS. YOU
CAN TASTE THE FRESH INGREDIENTS.
IT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
FLATBREAD PIZZA
OF THE DAY.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU IS GREAT.
YOUR CHOCOLATE BROWNIE
A LA MODE.
IT'S JUST REALLY FUN. SOMETIMES
WE COME REAL LATE NIGHT.
COMING FROM
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS,
IT IS TERRIBLY IMPOSSIBLE
TO EAT PAST 9:00,
AND SO THE GOAL WAS ALWAYS
TO BE OPEN LATE
AND SERVE
REALLY GOOD FOOD LATE.
CHICKEN TENDERS
CORDON BLEU.
THE OWNERS HERE UNDERSTAND
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR
AS FOOD PEOPLE.
PERFECT PLACE TO GO SIT DOWN,
RELAX, AND ENJOY A WELL-THOUGHT-
OUT COOKED-TO-PREPARED MEAL.
LIKE THIS TWIST
ON A PHILLY CLASSIC.
CHEESESTEAK EMPANADAS.
MELTED CHEESE WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF TRUFFLE, JUST DRIVES IT HOME.
AND FOR DIPPING...
IT'S A MIXTURE OF FLYING FISH
BEER AND GOODNESS.
WE ARE GOING TO MAKE
THE FLYING FISH SAUCE
FOR THE TRUFFLED
CHEESESTEAK EMPANADAS.
DIG IT.
GOT OUR HOT PAN.
LITTLE BIT OF OIL, MIREPOIX,
GARLIC, SALT, AND PEPPER.
CARAMELIZE THIS UNTIL
EVERYTHING'S NICE AND BROWN.
THEN WE POUR IN THE BEER.
THE BOURBON PORTER.
DO THEY REALLY PUT
BOURBON IN IT?
THEY DO.
WE'LL LET THAT REDUCE BY HALF.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
VEAL STOCK, POUR THAT IN.
YOU MAKE THE VEAL STOCK?
WE DO.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
LITTLE BIT OF HEAVY CREAM
AND MORE SALT AND PEPPER.
WE REDUCE THIS BY HALF AGAIN.
STRAIN IT INTO A FRESH, CLEAN
POT SO WE CAN FINISH IT OFF.
IT'S CRAZY.
IT'S ONE SAUCE FOR
A TRUFFLED CHEESESTEAK EMPANADA.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
WHAT ELSE?
DIJON MUSTARD,
WHOLE GRAIN MUSTARD,
SUGAR, BOURBON.
AND?
CARAMEL.
CARAMEL THAT YOU MAKE?
YEP.
OF COURSE.
I'M GONNA QUIT ASKING.
THAT'S IT. BRING IT TO A BOIL.
TIGHTEN IT UP WITH FLOUR WATER.
SIMMER IT JUST TILL
THAT FLOUR'S COOKED OUT.
15-20 MINUTES,
AND WE'RE DONE.
TIME FOR THE EMPANADA MEAT.
LIGHTLY OIL THE GRILL.
THINLY SLICED RIB EYE,
SPREAD THIS OUT.
WOW, MEGA THINLY SLICED.
SALT AND PEPPER.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT
IN CHEESESTEAK STYLE?
OH, YEAH. JUST TILL
THE MEAT'S COOKED THROUGH,
TAKE IT OFF THE GRILL,
LET IT COOL.
THE NEXT STEP, SEASON IT WITH
THE TRUFFLE OIL ALL OVER.
NOW IN WITH
AGED NEW YORK CHEDDAR.
MM-HMM.
FLUFF IT TOGETHER.
DEFINITELY SMELL THAT
TRUFFLE OIL RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
NOW WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA MAKE
OUR EMPANADAS.
CUT THE DOUGH FOR THE EMPANADA
DOWN TO THE MOLD SIZE.
WE USE A PIEROGI PRESS.
STICK THAT IN THERE.
PUT OUR FILLING IN.
LITTLE WASH TO SEAL IT,
SLAM IT SHUT.
GIVE IT A TIGHT SQUEEZE.
AND THEN IT'S READY TO ROCK.
NOW YOU'RE NOT FREEZING THESE
AHEAD OF TIME?
OH, NO.
THEY'RE MADE EVERY DAY.
SO YOU BUST THESE OUT,
DUST IT WITH A LITTLE FLOUR.
THEN WE GO TO THE FRYER.
HOW LONG DO THEY GO DOWN FOR?
THREE, FOUR MINUTES.
PULL THOSE OUT OF THE FRYER.
SERVE THIS
WITH FLYING FISH SAUCE.
YOU GOT IT.
TRUFFLED CHEESESTEAK EMPANADAS.
SMELL THAT.
MMM. OH. DELICIOUS.
THAT RIGHT THERE IS
A WORLD-CLASS EMPANADA.
COOKED PERFECTLY.
FILLING'S FANTASTIC.
THE CHEESESTEAK
LOVES THE TRUFFLE,
AND THE TRUFFLE
LOVES THE CHEESESTEAK.
AND THE FLYING FISH--
WHERE'S THAT BEEN ALL MY LIFE?
AWESOME JOB, CHEF,
AWESOME, AWESOME JOB.
EMPANADAS IN THE WINDOW.
CRISPY EXTERIOR,
MOIST INTERIOR. PERFECT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE EATING
AN ELEGANT CHEESESTEAK.
DEFINITELY A FUN TWIST.
PORK CHOP UP.
THEY'RE ALWAYS TRYING
TO UP THEIR GAME.
YOUR TINGA QUESADILLAS.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
THE FLAVOR JUST POPS PERFECTLY.
CHICKEN TENDERS UP.
GOOD FOOD, GOOD BEER,
GREAT STAFF.
REMEMBER, BE A GOOD DOG.
UP NEXT...
IT JUST FEELS LIKE
COMING HOME TO FAMILY.
WE'RE HEADED
TO SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
VEGGIES ARE LOOKING GOOD.
TO COOK...
LOOK AT THIS.
FROM THE BOOK.
THESE WERE SOME OF
MY GRANDMA SELMA'S RECIPES.
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D"
WE'VE GOT THE TAGLINE,
"IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT."
AND DO I HAVE A FUNKY ONE TODAY.
HERE WE ARE
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S IN AN OLD FARMHOUSE
THAT WAS MOVED TWICE
AND ONCE ACROSS THE FREEWAY
WITH THE FARMER'S TRUCK.
AND GET THIS,
THAT'S NOT EVEN THE FUNKY PART.
WAIT TILL YOU HEAR THEIR STORY
AND SEE WHAT THEY'RE COOKING.
THIS IS CHAPS.
STUFFED PORK CHOP ORDER UP.
SO SUMPTUOUS,
EVERYTHING YOU COULD HOPE FOR.
MUSHROOM AND BRIE SOUP.
FANTASTIC. IT'S PROBABLY
ONE OF MY FAVORITE ITEMS.
IT'S JUST LIKE NOTHING ELSE.
FIRE ON THE PORK CHOPS
RIGHT NOW.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
THE WAY OWNER CELESTE SHAW
REMEMBERS THEM...
VEGGIES ARE LOOKING GOOD.
FROM GROWING UP
ON HER GRANDPARENTS' FARM.
I WANTED TO RECREATE WHAT
MY LIFE WAS LIKE WITH THEM
FOR OTHER PEOPLE.
SO SHE OPENED THIS JOINT...
I THOUGHT, I CAN DO THIS.
WITH A LITTLE HELP
FROM GRANDMA.
LOOK AT THIS.
DON'T I LIKE NORWEGIAN?
HOW AWESOME IS THIS?
THESE WERE SOME OF
MY GRANDMA SELMA'S RECIPES.
LIKE GRANDMA'S BAKED OATMEAL...
LIKE NO OTHER OATMEAL
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
AND A FARMHOUSE TWIST
ON FRENCH TOAST.
IT DOESN'T LOOK
LIKE FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S NOT LIKE TOAST,
NOT LIKE BREAD. IT'S LIKE CAKE.
WITH BLUEBERRY-FLAVORED
SWEETENED CREAM CHEESE ON TOP.
SO THIS IS FROM
YOUR GRANDMOTHER'S RECIPE?
THAT'S CORRECT.
BLUEBERRY MUFFIN
FRENCH TOAST.
I ASSUME WE'RE MAKING
BLUEBERRY MUFFINS?
WE ARE MAKING
BLUEBERRY MUFFIN BREAD.
SO BUTTER.
WE'RE CREAMING THE BUTTER
RIGHT NOW.
WE CREAM THE BUTTER
AND THE SUGAR,
HEALTHY AMOUNT OF SUGAR.
FRESH EGGS.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
LITTLE BIT OF VANILLA.
OKAY.
KOSHER SALT.
AND THEN A LEAVENING AGENT.
YES, BAKING POWDER.
BLUEBERRIES.
YOU'RE KILLING
THE BLUEBERRIES.
NO, THE BLUEBERRIES ARE FINE.
SO THERE'S GONNA BE
NO CHUNK-AGE OF BLUEBERRY?
YOU'LL STILL SEE THAT LATER.
AND THE FLOUR.
A.P.?
YES.
YOU'RE CRUSHING
THE BLUEBERRY.
THEY DON'T GET CRUSHED.
YOU CAN DO IT.
I CAN DO IT.
A LITTLE AQUA NET.
DON'T WANT YOUR BREAD
TO STICK.
SO WE'LL GO TO THE PAN.
THAT IT?
I THINK WE'RE GOOD.
WANT TO LICK THE BOWL?
IT'S GOOD, HUH?
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
IN THE OVEN HOW LONG?
ABOUT AN HOUR.
SO THE BLUEBERRY MUFFIN BREAD
IS COOKING.
NOW WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
THE EGG WASH
FOR THE FRENCH TOAST.
GO AHEAD, FIRE IT UP.
OKAY. WHOLE EGGS.
OKAY.
A LITTLE WATER.
JUST MIX IT UP
LIKE A SIMPLE WASH.
WE JUST PUT IT ASIDE.
NEXT, SUGAR AND CREAM CHEESE.
WE MAKE A FROSTING THAT GOES ON
THE TOP OF THE FRENCH TOAST.
COOL.
IT'S CREAM CHEESE,
MORE SUGAR.
18 POUNDS OF SUGAR
IN THERE.
BLUEBERRIES.
NOW YOU'RE REALLY KILLING
THE BLUEBERRIES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA KILL 'EM.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
PURE PURPLE FROSTING.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
I KNOW.
NOW WHAT?
WE'LL GET THE FRENCH TOAST OUT
AND DRESS IT UP.
SO IT'S COOLED DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SLICE IT?
SLICE IT AND GET IT
READY TO GRILL.
WOW, YOU'RE MAKING
HONKING CHUNKS.
YEAH.
HONKING CHUNKS IS A SCANDINAVIAN
WORD FOR LARGE PIECE.
(laughs)
THINK IT'S GONNA COME UNDONE?
DID YOU HIT IT
WITH ENOUGH AQUA NET?
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
YOU DIDN'T BEAT
THE BLUEBERRIES UP THAT BAD.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT THING.
ALL RIGHT.
NO CINNAMON, NO NADA
IN THERE.
NOTHING, JUST THE REGULAR
EGG WASH.
MORE BUTTER?
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
PUT THE BACON ON.
TWO PIECES?
WHO ARE YOU TRYING TO TEASE
WITH THAT?
IT'S A BIG PIECE
OF FRENCH TOAST.
OH!
ISN'T THAT BEAUTIFUL?
IT IS BEAUTIFUL. ARE WE READY
FOR THE WHOLE PACKAGE DEAL?
WE ARE.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE FROSTING
ON THE FRENCH TOAST.
OKAY. HOW DO YOU ATTACK THIS?
FORK, FROST,
BREAK INTO.
SYRUP NOT REQUIRED.
MMM. SUPER MOIST,
WARM ALL THE WAY THROUGH,
TRUE BLUEBERRY FLAVOR.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF THE ACID
FROM THE CREAM CHEESE.
IT'S NOT OVERLY SWEET.
AND JUST LOOK AT HOW MOIST
YET CRUMBLY THAT IS.
I MEAN, THIS IS OVER-THE-TOP,
REALLY NICE.
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF FRENCH TOAST,
NEVER HAD IT
WITH BLUEBERRY MUFFIN CAKE.
MY KIDS WOULD--MATTER OF FACT,
MY KIDS ARE GONNA SEE THIS.
I'M GONNA BE MAKING THIS
ON SUNDAY.
BLUEBERRY MUFFIN
FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S JUST WONDERFUL.
(man) ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
I LOVE THIS STUFF.
I FEEL LIKE I'M EATING DESSERT,
BUT IT'S BREAKFAST.
JUST AMAZING FRENCH TOAST.
HOW LONG
YOU BEEN COMING HERE?
SINCE RIGHT AFTER IT WAS MOVED
ACROSS THE FREEWAY
AND OPENED UP.
THIS IS THE OLD HOUSE?
THIS IS THE ORIGINAL HOUSE
THAT I BOUGHT AND MOVED.
IT WAS THAT PORTION THAT
WAS BROUGHT OVER, CORRECT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
IS THIS WHAT YOU THOUGHT
IT WAS GONNA TURN INTO?
I DIDN'T REALIZE
WE WOULD END UP THIS BIG.
HOW ARE YOU?
BUT I KNEW IT WOULD BE A PLACE
THAT PEOPLE WOULD EXPERIENCE
THE KIND OF COMFORT
YOU'D ONLY HAVE IN A FARMHOUSE.
LIKE BEEF STROGANOFF...
WONDERFUL, HUGE SERVING.
I ALWAYS HAVE TO SHARE IT
WITH SOMEONE.
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK...
ORDER UP.
AND A MADE-TO-ORDER
STUFFED PORK CHOP.
WE CUT OUR OWN PORK...
OKAY.
AND WE ORDER IT FRESH
EVERY DAY.
(man) IT'S DELICIOUS,
SINGED ON THE OUTSIDE
BUT REALLY JUICY IN THE MIDDLE.
IT'S JUST FILLED
WITH MELTY GOODNESS INSIDE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A DRY RUB.
FOR THE STUFFED PORK CHOP.
MOST OF THE MEAT
AND SOME OF THE FILLINGS
GET THIS HOUSE SEASONING.
OKAY, WELL, GO AHEAD.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
GARLIC, THYME, PAPRIKA...
NICE COLOR.
KOSHER SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY, NOW WHAT'S
THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA USE
THE HOUSE SPICE,
MAKE THE FILLING
FOR THE PORK CHOP.
RICOTTA.
GOAT CHEESE.
PINE NUTS.
HOUSE SEASONING.
SOME SUN-DRIEDS.
INTERESTING.
SO NOW WE GOT THIS READY.
CUT THE CHOP, DO THE STUFF.
LET'S DO IT.
HOLY HOG. WHAT SUPER PIG
DID YOU GET THAT FROM?
THAT LOOKS LIKE
A 900-POUNDER.
EVERY DAY WE GET
AN ENTIRE LOIN LIKE THIS
TO DO PORK CHOPS FOR DINNER.
BONELESS, THOUGH, HUH?
BONELESS. WELL--
THE BONE-IN
IS THE FLAVOR-IN.
NO, YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
IT'S GOOD-LOOKING MEAT.
LITTLE POCKET.
NOT TOO DEEP, DON'T WANT
TO POKE THROUGH, GOT IT.
I'M GONNA FILL IT UP.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
AND THEN YOU JUST HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE SPRINKLE
OF THE HOUSE RUB.
SO WE'LL GO TO THE PAN.
IT'S READY FOR THE SAUTé.
CLARIFIED BUTTER, I BET.
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA SEAR THE PORK CHOP.
THERE YOU GO. SO WE'LL JUST
MARK IT ON BOTH SIDES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR WHITE WINE.
FINISH IT IN THE OVEN
AT ABOUT 250 FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 9 MINUTES.
SO WE LET THAT GO. WHAT ARE
WE GONNA SERVE THIS WITH?
THE SWEET POTATOES.
THE SWEET POTATOES
AND A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR
AND ALSO SOME MORE BUTTER.
VEGGIES ARE DONE.
PORK CHOP.
RIGHT OUT OF THE OVEN.
ALL RIGHT,
NICE COLORFUL PLATE.
LOOK AT THAT,
PERFECTLY COOKED.
MMM. NICE LITTLE CRUST
TO THE PORK CHOP
AND ALL THAT JUICE.
TELL YOU WHAT,
IT'S NOT LACKING IN FLAVOR.
YOU GET A GOOD AMOUNT OF SALT
AND TANG
BETWEEN THE RICOTTA
AND THE GOAT CHEESE
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
THE SUN-DRIED TOMATO.
THE KEY IS THAT THE PORK CHOP
IS COOKED PERFECTLY.
THAT IS THE ABSOLUTE KEY.
NICE AND JUICY,
GREAT FILLING TO IT,
WIDE VARIETY OF FLAVORS--
THAT'S A PERFECT EXAMPLE OF
A STUFFED FARMHOUSE PORK CHOP.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(woman) STUFFED PORK CHOP.
IT IS HEAVENLY.
RICH AND SAVORY--IT'S JUST LIKE
BEING FED A HOME-COOKED MEAL.
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH ORDER UP.
(woman) BREAKFAST, LUNCH,
OR DINNER--
IT JUST FEELS LIKE
COMING HOME TO FAMILY.
GOOD MORNING.
THE WARMEST,
MOST WONDERFUL FEELING.
(woman) THIS PLACE
IS JUST AS MUCH ABOUT THE LOVE
AS IT IS THE FOOD.
IT'S TOTALLY CELESTE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
GOOD JOB.
NEXT STOP...
WE'RE RIGHT ON THE PIER.
WE'RE HEADED
TO PORTLAND, MAINE...
LOBSTER ROLL COMING UP.
WHERE WHEN THEY SAY
FRESH SEAFOOD...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THEY AREN'T KIDDING.
WHOA.
I'M HERE IN PORTLAND, MAINE,
ON THE CUSTOM HOUSE WHARF
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'D BEEN A HANGOUT
FOR LOBSTERMEN, FISHERMEN,
AND FERRY PASSENGERS
SINCE 1929.
NOW THIS JOINT HAS SEEN ITS
GOOD TIMES AND ITS BAD TIMES,
BUT IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
ON ITS WAY OUT
HAD IT NOT BEEN FOR
A LOCAL BUSINESSMAN
THAT DIDN'T WANT TO SEE
A PORTLAND LANDMARK GO AWAY.
THIS IS THE PORTHOLE RESTAURANT.
LOBSTER SANDWICH.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
IT'S REALLY A PART OF MAINE
AND A PART OF PORTLAND.
AND OLIVER KEITHLY...
HOW ARE YOU? (laughs)
WANTED TO KEEP IT THAT WAY.
I WAS REALLY CONCERNED
THAT THE DEVELOPMENT
ON THE WATERFRONT WOULD PUSH
A PLACE LIKE THIS OUT.
SO HE BOUGHT IT...
HOW WAS EVERYTHING, GUYS?
BROUGHT IN LOCAL CHEF
PAUL DYER...
A LOBSTER ROLL COMING UP.
AND KEPT A PORTLAND TRADITION
ALIVE.
I GOT A BOWL OF CLAM CHOWDER.
THERE'S COMPLETE OLD CHARM
ABOUT THIS BUILDING
AND ABOUT THIS RESTAURANT.
CORNED BEEF HASH,
EGGS OVER MEDIUM.
RIGHT ON THE PIER--THE SEAFOOD'S
COMING IN FRESH.
THIS IS YOUR LOBSTER POT
RIGHT HERE?
THIS IS OUR LOBSTER POT.
YOU BRING IT UP,
AND HE'S THE RIGHT SIZE.
PUT THAT ON.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THE LOBSTER'S PERFECT.
IT COMES RIGHT FROM THE WATER,
RIGHT ONTO THE TABLE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CAN'T GET ANY FRESHER
THAN THIS OR ANY BETTER.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA BOIL LOBSTERS
FOR OUR LOBSTER SANDWICH.
WE GOT A BOILING BROTH.
WHAT'S IN THIS?
JUST LEMONS.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA
SUBMERGE THEM INTO?
YEP.
SEE YOU IN THE SANDWICH.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
10, 15 MINUTES.
YEP.
PULL 'EM OUT, COOL 'EM DOWN.
YOU GOT IT.
DIG IT. LOOK AT THOSE.
SO THESE WERE CAUGHT TODAY.
CAUGHT TODAY.
NOW WE BREAK 'EM DOWN.
GIVE ME THE BREAKDOWN.
BREAKDOWN? SHOW ME THE VOODOO
THAT YOU DO.
START OFF-
BREAK THE CLAWS OFF.
TAKE THE TAIL OFF,
CUT THE TAIL IN HALF
AND REMOVE THE MEAT
FROM THE TAIL AND THE CLAWS.
SO THIS WILL
ALL GET CHOPPED UP,
AND THEN WE CAN MAKE
THE LOBSTER SANDWICH.
YEP.
SO THE LOBSTER ROLL
DOESN'T COME
ON THE ICONIC HOT DOG
BUN-LOOKING LOBSTER ROLL?
THIS COMES ON BRIOCHE
THAT YOU MAKE YOURSELF?
YOU GOT IT.
WHAT DO WE START WITH?
WE START WITH EGGS.
(squeals)
EGGS ARE IN.
FRESH YEAST.
THEN WE ADD SOME MILK.
MILK AT ROOM TEMPERATURE
TO GIVE THE YEAST
A LITTLE EXTRA KICK.
ADD SOME A.P. FLOUR,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT, SUGAR,
AND THEN WE GOT SOME BUTTER.
AND THEN IT'S MIX?
AND THEN IT'S MIX TIME--
FIVE TO TEN MINUTES.
OKAY, SO IT HANGS OUT
FOR A DAY IN THE WALK-IN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
BREAK IT DOWN.
TOSS A LITTLE FLOUR,
CUT IT RIGHT IN HALF
INTO TWO LOAVES, PUSH IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA ROLL IT UP
IN A NICE TIGHT LOAF.
YOU GONNA GREASE
THOSE PANS?
NO. THE BUTTER THAT'S ALREADY
IN THE DOUGH, THEY DON'T SEEM
TO STICK WHATSOEVER
SO IT WORKS OUT PRETTY GOOD.
SO THAT'S IT.
GO IN THE PROOFER?
EXACTLY.
OKAY. ONCE IT PROOFS,
IT'LL HIT THE OVEN,
EGG WASH RIGHT AT THE VERY END,
GIVES IT A NICE COLOR.
GOT IT. NOW AIOLI.
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA USE
TO MIX THE LOBSTER
TO MAKE THE LOBSTER SANDWICH.
WITH SOME ANCHOVY.
I'M IMPRESSED.
WE GOT EGG YOLKS,
FRESH GARLIC,
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE,
TABASCO, SALT, PEPPER,
OUR ANCHOVIES.
LEMON JUICE--MY MOUTH'S
STARTING TO WATER.
A LITTLE DIJON HERE.
A LITTLE EMULSIFYING AGENT,
AND THEN THE DRIZZLE.
DRIZZLE OF THE OIL.
OLIVE OIL?
THIS IS A MIX--90/10.
A BLEND. YEP.
YOU CAN HEAR IT KIND OF
SLOW DOWN AND THICKEN UP.
MMM. THAT'S SO RICH
AND CREAMY.
IT ALMOST TASTES LIKE BUTTER.
LET'S MAKE A SANDWICH.
WE SHOULD.
THIS IS THE BRIOCHE.
NICE CRUST ON IT.
LET IT REST A LITTLE BIT,
THEN SLICE INTO IT.
THROW 'EM ON THE FLATTOP?
THROW 'EM ON THE FLATTOP,
GRILL 'EM WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
AWESOME.
AND TOSS THIS AIOLI RIGHT IN
WITH THE LOBSTER.
VERY LITTLE AIOLI.
THIS IS NICELY BROWNED. I KNOW
WHY YOU NEED THE BRIOCHE.
YOU'RE PUTTING, LIKE, A 15-POUND
LOBSTER ON THAT THING.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE
YOU GET ENOUGH.
THAT'S A PRETTY FAT SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THAT--PRETTY THICK.
MMM. I'M A BREAD JUNKIE.
SO RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
I'M A FAN.
THE BUTTERINESS
OF THE LOBSTER--MMM.
I WOULDN'T CALL IT
INTENSE FLAVOR,
BUT THE AIOLI
JUST REALLY ACCENTUATES IT,
AND THAT'S A LOT OF LOBSTER
IN THERE.
THE TOASTED BREAD,
CREAMY LOBSTER, THE AIOLI PLUS--
DUDE, A LOT
OF LOBSTER SANDWICHES OUT THERE,
BUT THIS ONE
HAS ITS OWN IDENTITY. I DIG IT.
LOBSTER SANDWICH
ON BRIOCHE.
IT'S DELICIOUS. IT'S GOT
A NICE LEMONY FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S FALLING OUT
OF THE SANDWICH,
THEY PUT SO MUCH IN THERE--
DEFINITELY REALLY FRESH.
AND FOR THESE GUYS,
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY TO ROLL...
I GOT A FRIED SCALLOP
COMING UP.
WE JUST TRY AND KEEP IT LOCAL
AS MUCH AS WE CAN.
VERY LOCAL--DIRECTLY FROM
THE FISHERMAN.
YOU KNOW, IT DOESN'T GET
ANY FRESHER THAN THAT.
FROM HADDOCK...
THEY MADE A NICE AND LIGHT
HADDOCK SANDWICH.
TO SQUID...
(whistles) SQUID COMES IN
FRESH IN THIS AREA?
YEP.
FOR THE FRESH
GINGER CALAMARI.
NICE COMBO. YOU WOULDN'T THINK
TO PUT THOSE TWO TOGETHER.
BUT HE DID.
FRIED GINGER SQUID
IN THE WINDOW.
DIG THIS. OKAY.
SO WHAT'S THE BREAKDOWN?
FIRST THING WE START DOING,
WE CUT THE TENTACLE RIGHT HERE,
PULL THIS WHOLE MEMBRANE
RIGHT OUT.
THE ONLY THING YOU GOTTA PULL
OUT HERE IS A BIG PIECE
OF CARTILAGE
THAT THEY CALL A PEN.
THAT'S ALL HE HAD
HOLDING HIM TOGETHER.
THAT'S ALL HE'S GOT HOLDING
HIM TOGETHER. WE'LL CUT IT.
FRESH CALAMARI.
YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT TENDER?
YOU CANNOT BEAT THIS.
CALAMARI.
ONCE IT'S CUT UP, WE SOAK IT
OVERNIGHT IN THE BUTTERMILK,
AND THEN EACH ORDER WILL GET
TOSSED IN A DRIED GINGER DREDGE.
THE DREDGE IS SIMPLE--
JUST ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
POWDERED GINGER, PEPPER, SALT.
TOSS THAT ALL TOGETHER.
TOSS THIS IN A BOWL.
I CAN SMELL THAT GINGER
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
YEAH, THE SWEETNESS BETWEEN
THE BUTTERMILK AND THE GINGER
REALLY SEEMS TO GIVE IT
A GOOD FLAVOR.
WE'LL DROP THIS
IN THE FRYER.
YEP.
350. THAT'S A MONSTER PORTION.
THAT LEMON AIOLI
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
I LIKE IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF FRESH LEMON
ON TOP.
YOU SQUEEZE IT YOURSELF
ON THERE AHEAD OF TIME
BEFORE IT GOES OUT
TO THE GUESTS?
YEP.
I'M A FAN OF THAT.
SERVE IT TO THE GUESTS
THE WAY YOU WANT THEM TO EAT IT.
I MEAN, THE CALAMARI HAS ITS OWN
FLAVOR RIGHT FROM THE GET-GO.
A LITTLE BITE OF THE BUTTERMILK,
A LITTLE HINT OF THE GINGER.
TALK ABOUT CALAMARI
BEING TENDER.
THIS HAS CHEW TO IT,
BUT IT'S TENDER.
THAT'S GOTTA
BE FROM BEING FRESH.
YOU FIND CALAMARI THAT IS THAT
FRESH, HAND-BATTERED SERVED
WITH JUST A LITTLE BIT OF AIOLI,
A SQUEEZE OF SOME LEMON--
THAT'S GREAT STUFF.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT.
THANKS, MAN.
(woman) FRIED GINGER SQUID.
CALAMARI--WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT HAS A KICK TO IT.
THE GINGER FLAVOR
REALLY SETS IT APART.
LOBSTER LOLLIPOP
IN THE WINDOW.
I'VE NEVER HAD
A BAD MEAL HERE.
GREAT LUNCH,
THEY HAVE GREAT DINNER.
I DO ENJOY THEIR BREAKFASTS
QUITE A BIT.
EGGS BENEDICT IN THE WINDOW.
BREAKFAST TIME, THERE ARE
LOBSTERMEN, THERE ARE LAWYERS
SITTING SIDE BY SIDE.
AND STARTING THE DAY
PAUL'S WAY...
THIS BRISKET HASH
IS JUST OUTSTANDING.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
I'M GONNA LIKE THIS.
AT THE PORTHOLE RESTAURANT
IN PORTLAND, MAINE...
I GOT A FRIED SCALLOP
COMING UP.
OWNER OLIVER KEITHLY...
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
HAS BEEN SERVING UP THE LOCAL
CATCH FOR MORE THAN A DECADE...
EVERYTHING'S COMING IN DAILY
FRESH.
STARTING THE DAY OFF
FOR THE GUYS BRINGING IT IN...
HERE YOU GO, PAUL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND THE REST OF THE REGULARS,
TOO.
BREAKFAST TIME, THERE ARE
LOBSTERMEN, THERE ARE LAWYERS
SITTING SIDE BY SIDE.
BREAKFAST IN THE SUMMER ON
THE DECK WHEN IT'S A NICE DAY.
NOTHING BETTER.
BLUEBERRY PANCAKE.
THE PANCAKES ARE AWESOME--
CLASSIC MAINE DISH.
FLIPPING THE HASH, GUYS.
HOW'S THE HASH?
THE HASH IS OUTSTANDING.
WITH CHEF PAUL DYER'S
OWN SPIN.
HASH IS UP.
HE'S NOT BRINING HIS BEEF.
HE'S BOILING IT.
IT'S BRISKET SIMMERED
PERFECTLY--FABULOUS.
WHAT'S THIS
GOING TOGETHER FOR?
OUR HASH
FOR OUR HASH AND EGGS.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'LL TOSS IN OUR MIREPOIX
WITH ONIONS, THE CARROTS...
AND THE CELERY?
AND CELERY.
FANTASTIC.
BRISKET GOES IN.
WHERE DID THIS RECIPE
COME FROM?
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT.
SO THIS IS JUST à LA PAUL?
à LA PAUL.
à LA PAUL. YOU'RE JUST GONNA
SIMMER WITH THE MIREPOIX
THREE TO FOUR HOURS.
THREE TO FOUR--YEP.
I WANT TO SEE
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN
WITH THIS SIMMER MIREPOIX.
WE'LL FIND OUT.
SO WE STRAIN THE BRISKET
FROM THE VEGGIES.
YEP.
NOW SHE'S GONNA HEAD
INTO THE FLOOR MIXER.
AND LOOK AT ALL THE FAT
THAT'S STILL ON THAT.
THAT'S GOING IN THIS MIX.
MOST OF THAT
WILL BE MIXED RIGHT UP.
WHEN YOU BLEND THAT FAT
INTO THE MEAT,
IT'S GONNA ADD
A LOT OF OF FLAVOR.
FRESH POTATOES.
THAT'S ALL THE POTATO
THAT GOES IN?
THAT GOES IN.
THAT WAS ABOUT 15 POUNDS
OF MEAT, 2 POUNDS OF POTATOES.
MAYBE.
I'M GONNA LIKE THIS.
SAUTéED ONIONS,
FRESH THYME, GARLIC.
YOU DON'T HOLD BACK AT
THE SEASONING SECTION, DO YOU?
NO.
WHEN IT SAW IT GETTING BOILED
WITH THE MIREPOIX...
A LITTLE WORRIED?
I THOUGHT,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA HAVE?
WE'RE GONNA
HAVE BOILED O'HASH?
FRESH MUSTARD, SALT,
AND PEPPER.
AND THEN HIT THE THROTTLE?
HIT THE THROTTLE.
THAT PROBABLY IS ONE
OF THE MOST UNIQUE
HASH-MAKING EXPERIENCES
I'VE HAD.
IT'S DEFINITELY
A LITTLE DIFFERENT,
BUT WE SELL A LOT OF IT.
IT'S CALLED CRAZY HASH.
CRAZY HASH. I'LL PUT
A HANDFUL ON THE GRILL.
PATTY IT OUT.
WE'LL THROW THE WEIGHT
RIGHT ON IT,
GET IT NICE AND CRISPY.
AND GET NICE.
NOW I'LL FLIP IT.
WE'VE GOT EGGS READY. MMM!
HASH READY?
YEP. WE GOTTA GET NICE
AND CRISPY ON BOTH SIDES.
NOW YOU GET TWO FRESH EGGS
RIGHT ON TOP.
SO LIKE I SAID,
THERE'S BARELY THAT MUCH POTATO
INSIDE OF THIS.
HMM. LOTS OF FLAVOR.
IT ALMOST TASTES TO ME
LIKE A CROSS BETWEEN
A BRISKET SANDWICH AND HASH.
MMM. GREAT CRUST,
A TON OF MEAT,
A LITTLE BIT OF POTATO
JUST TO CREAM IT UP A BIT.
FOR HASH LOVERS,
YOU'LL LIKE THIS.
I'D EAT THAT ALL DAY LONG.
AWESOME.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
HASH IN THE WINDOW.
THE HASH HERE
IS JUST FANTASTIC.
IT'S REALLY GOOD,
REALLY HEARTY.
I FEEL AS IF MY GRANDMOTHER'S
IN THE KITCHEN MAKING IT.
CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT IT'S REALLY TENDER.
THE BRISKET HASH
IS JUST OUTSTANDING.
I WANT THIS ON SOME BRIOCHE
WITH A LOBSTER ON THE SIDE.
LOBSTER BENEDICT
IN THE WINDOW.
ON A BEAUTIFUL DAY LIKE TODAY,
YOU CAN'T BEAT SITTING OUTSIDE
AND ENJOYING GREAT FOOD.
REUBEN'S READY--
JUST NEEDS FRIES.
IT'S REALLY A MEETING PLACE
OF THE WATERFRONTS.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL. YOU'VE GOT
THE LOBSTER BOATS COMING IN.
YOU GOT A GREAT SETUP,
A GREAT FEEL. CONGRATS, MAN.
THANKS, DUDE.
GREAT JOINT.
PLEASURE MEETING YOU, MAN.
LIKE WE ALWAYS SAY,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT THESE
RECIPES, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WANT TO SMELL IT?
(laughter)
(man) OKAY, SHALL WE STOP?
(laughing)