HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOA! DUDE,
THAT IS AWESOME.
WINGS...
I LOVE 'EM.
AND THINGS.
COCONUT GINGER PEANUT BRITTLE.
IN BELMAR, NEW JERSEY...
SMOTHERED BURRITO.
THE JOINT IN A STRIP MALL...
FRESH FOOD, UNIQUE FOOD.
MAKING AUTHENTIC
MEXICAN FAVORITES...
PORK MOLE PLATTER.
LIKE WINGS?
MMM. GOSH, DUDE.
THESE ARE ROCKIN'.
IN COEUR d'ALENE, IDAHO...
A GREAT PLACE TO COME.
THE SPORTS BAR...
HOW'S THE PIE TONIGHT?
ROLLING OUT THE BURGERS...
MMM! THAT BUN
IS OFF THE HOOK.
AND PITCHIN' OUT THE PIES.
EXCELLENT.
AND IN NASHVILLE...
RICE-N-PEAS...
(woman) YES, MA'AM.
THE LOCAL FAVORITE...
SO THIS IS REAL JAMAICAN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHERE A QUICK LUNCH...
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
MEANS OXTAIL...
MMM.
AND MANGO CHUTNEY CHICKEN.
IF YOU LIKE FRIED CHICKEN,
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WHEN I SAY "NEW JERSEY,"
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
YOU'RE THINKING DINER CAPITAL.
ALONG WITH THOSE GREAT DINERS,
THEY'VE GOT
SOME FUNKY LITTLE JOINTS
LIKE THE ONE I'M HERE
TO VISIT TODAY,
45 MINUTES SOUTH
OF NEW YORK CITY
IN BELMAR, NEW JERSEY,
THIS IS
10th AVENUE BURRITO COMPANY.
SMOTHERED BURRITO.
SMOTHERED IN CHIPOTLE CREAM
SAUCE--ABSOLUTELY PHENOMENAL.
CHICKEN TORTILLA SOUP.
IT IS THE BEST.
THIS, TO ME, IS LIKE FOOD
THAT WE FIND IN CALIFORNIA.
FIRING A CORN SOUP.
BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE JERSEY BOY
BRIAN KATZ FELL IN LOVE
WITH THIS KIND
OF MEXICAN FOOD...
FIRING PORK MOLE.
AND LEARNED TO COOK, TOO.
WENT FOR A JOB ONE DAY, AND I'VE
BEEN IN THE KITCHEN EVER SINCE.
AND AFTER DECADES
IN THE BIZ...
TEQUILA LIME SHRIMP.
HE BROUGHT HIS OWN TAKE
ON MEXICAN HOME TO JERSEY.
AMAZING. YOU CAN'T GET ANY
MEXICAN LIKE THIS AROUND HERE.
I JUST LIKE
TO LET PEOPLE EXPERIMENT
WITH NEW
AND DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
LIKE A MEXICAN SPIN
ON CHICKEN WINGS.
ADOBO WINGS.
I'VE NEVER MADE ADOBO SAUCE.
AND THAT GETS TOSSED
ON THE WINGS.
THAT GETS TOSSED
I'M GONNA
CHECK THOSE OUT LATER,
BUT FIRST,
THIS MEXICAN CLASSIC.
PORK MOLE PLATTER.
PORK MOLE--I LOVE IT.
IT'S AMAZING.
HUGE CHUNKS OF PORK WITH PEPPERS
AND, LIKE, A MOLE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE MOLE SAUCE
THAT GOES INTO THE PORK MOLE.
GET THIS MOLE MOVING.
ANCHO PASILLA PEPPERS.
MULATO?
YEP.
ALL THE PEPPERS ARE GONNA
GET A LITTLE BIT OF A TOAST.
YEAH, AND IT'S GONNA GO
RIGHT HERE INTO THE STOCKPOT.
HIT A LITTLE WATER,
LET THEM STEEP.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
COVER IT UP.
IT'S HIGH-TECH.
I MEAN, THAT ALMOST FITS
LIKE A GLOVE.
ALMOST. AND WE'RE GONNA TOAST
THE REST OF OUR INGREDIENTS.
CORN TORTILLAS--LET THESE GET
A LITTLE GOLDEN BROWN.
SET 'EM ASIDE.
WHOLE ALMONDS.
TOAST THESE UNTIL
THEY'RE A LITTLE FRAGRANT.
JUST GONNA PUT THAT RIGHT HERE.
ADD A LITTLE CORIANDER.
SESAME SEEDS.
A LITTLE ANISE.
ANISE?!
ANISE. WE'RE GONNA
LET IT COOL DOWN.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
EVERYTHING TO THE ROBOT COUPE.
CLOVES--NOT TOO MANY--
GARLIC, SOME CINNAMON.
AMON-AMON-AMON-AMON.
BLACK PEPPER AS WELL.
JUST A TOUCH.
CHOCOLATE--PULSE THIS.
VERY SUBTLE
WITH THESE THINGS.
IT'S GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR.
AND NEXT, WE'RE JUST GONNA
RIP UP THE CORN TORTILLAS
THAT WE TOASTED OFF,
ALL THE SEEDS AND ALMONDS.
GET AFTER IT!
MAKE IT YOURS. OWN THAT!
GO AHEAD
AND ADD THE CHOPPED TOMATOES,
SOME CHOPPED ONION,
ADD SOME RAISINS, PULSE ALL
THIS STUFF TOGETHER NOW.
REHYDRATED PEPPERS.
CAN WE ACTUALLY PUT ON
THE "ON" BUTTON?
PUT IT ON. JUST GET IT DOWN
TO A NICE PASTE.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
COOK THIS DOWN.
WE GOT OUR STOCK POT--
A TABLESPOON OF OIL.
LE MOLE.
SO YOU LEAVE YOURS
JUST A BIT CHUNKY, THOUGH.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
I LOVE THE ALMOND COMPONENT.
LIQUID THAT WE REHYDRATED
THE PEPPERS IN.
GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE STIR.
LET IT JUST COME TO A BOIL.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD IN SUGAR
AND SALT.
LET THAT SIMMER FOR ABOUT
ANOTHER 10, 15 MINUTES?
AND THEN WE'LL PUT THAT
ON THE SEARED PORK?
YES, WE WILL.
GREAT.
SEASON OUR PORK WITH KOSHER
SALT, CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
AND A REAL SMALL AMOUNT
OF THIS SPICE POWDER
THAT A BUDDY OF MINE
MAKES UP.
IT'S THAT POTENT, THAT
THAT'S ALL YOU PUT ON THERE?
YES, IT IS.
NO.
GO AHEAD. A WHOLE BUNCH OF
DIFFERENT GROUND CHILIES,
HABANERO BEING
THE MAIN COMPONENT.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA SEASON
THE OTHER SIDE.
(whistles)
THAT STUFF'S SMOKIN'!
YEAH, JUST...
(high-pitched voice) WOW!
JUST A LITTLE OIL.
WE GOT FAT SIDE DOWN.
(whistles)
(normal voice) SO WE'LL SEAR
BOTH SIDES. LOOK AT THAT.
YEP. WE'LL GET
A LITTLE COLOR ON IT.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD
THE REST OF OUR INGREDIENTS IN.
GO.
GREEN BELL PEPPER,
POBLANO PEPPERS, ONIONS...
LOOK AT THIS.
WATCH. OHH!
GROUND GARLIC, GROUND CUMIN...
COMINO.
SOME OREGANO, GONNA ADD
SOME DRIED THYME,
A FEW BAY LEAVES...
GETTIN' GANGSTER
WITH THE BAY LEAVES.
MORE BLACK PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT.
I HELPED.
AND A LITTLE BIT MORE
SPICE POWDER, TOMATO.
YOU COOK LIKE I DO--
JUST A FEW KEY INGREDIENTS.
ADD SOME WATER TO COVER, AND AS
SOON AS THIS COMES TO A BOIL--
COVERED OR UNCOVERED?
WE'LL LEAVE IT UNCOVERED.
NOW WE HIT THE MOLE?
YEP.
THAT'S GOOD-LOOKIN' MOLE,
MAN.
THIS IS GONNA SIMMER
FOR HOW MANY HOURS?
THREE AND A HALF.
UNTIL IT SHREDS APART.
TILL IT SHREDS APART.
NUTS. ALL RIGHT.
SIMMER DOWN, BREAK DOWN.
NICE AND TENDER. PUT
A LITTLE RICE ON THE BOTTOM.
GENEROUS WITH THAT.
FRESH-SHREDDED
MONTEREY JACK CHEESE,
SHREDDED LETTUCE,
DICED TOMATO,
FRESH-MADE PICO de GALLO,
AND JUST FINISH IT ALL OFF
WITH SOUR CREAM HERE,
AND THAT'S OUR
PORK MOLE PLATTER.
THAT'S AWESOME.
IT'S A GREAT MOLE, BUDDY.
I COULD EAT THAT ALL DAY LONG.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE
BIG CHUNKS OF PEPPERS. MMM.
PORK FALLS APART,
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT--
OLD-SCHOOL REAL-DEAL
MEXICAN COOK-DOWN.
(mumbling) DELICIOUS.
GET AWAY FROM ME...
HERE'S THE PORK MOLE.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING THAT I'VE EVER HAD
IS WONDERFUL.
(woman) TILAPIA TACOS.
HE USES FRESH INGREDIENTS.
WE GET OUR PRODUCE EVERY SINGLE
DAY, MARINATE OUR OWN MEATS.
NOTHING COMES OUT OF CAN.
NOTHING COMES OUT OF JAR.
NOT THE SALSA...
THE SALSA'S THE BEST HERE.
NOT THE GUACAMOLE...
SO FRESH--
THE SPICES ARE WONDERFUL.
AND NOT THIS MEXICAN FAVORITE.
THE ADOBO SAUCE
IS OUTRAGEOUS.
WHICH BRINGS US BACK
TO THOSE WINGS.
(Brian) ADOBO WINGS.
I LOVE 'EM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
ADOBO SAUCE.
ADOBO BEING THE RED
TOMATO SAUCE WITH VINEGAR...
THE RED TOMATO SAUCE.
THAT RECONSTITUTES
THE CHIPOTLES...
ABSOLUTELY.
WHICH IS A SMOKED JALAPEÑO.
ADD 'EM RIGHT HERE.
OKAY.
PUT THE STRAINER IN THE POT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
EVERYTHING IN THE STRAINER.
OKAY.
WHOLE HEADS OF GARLIC,
THE ONIONS IN THERE.
WOW, THIS IS COOL.
CINNAMON STICKS--A LITTLE
SWEETNESS WITH THE HEAT--
THYME, THE OREGANO.
LIKE A CUP.
JUST ABOUT.
THROW SOME BAY LEAVES.
PILONCILLO.
OH, HO HO!
THIS--CRYSTALLIZED HARD
MEXICAN SUGAR.
AWESOME!
YEAH, AND JUST A FEW CLOVES,
ORANGES,
WATER,
STRAIGHT-UP WHITE VINEGAR,
AND THIS IS PINEAPPLE AND ORANGE
THAT I JUST LET STEEP
IN COLD WATER FOR A FEW DAYS.
LET THAT COOK DOWN FOR ABOUT
THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THIS HAS SIMMERED.
STRAIN OUT ALL OF THE SOLIDS
FROM THE ADOBO.
LOOK AT HOW THEY SOAK UP
ALL THAT JUICE.
A LITTLE TOMATO PURéE,
LET IT BOIL OUT,
THEN GO AHEAD
AND GIVE THIS A, UH...
(imitates motor revving)
HOW MUCH LONGER
ARE WE GONNA LET THIS SIMMER?
FOR ABOUT ANOTHER
15 OR 20 MINUTES.
I DON'T FEEL
ANY MORE CHUNKS, BOSS.
I THINK WE'RE GOOD
TO GO THEN.
AHH.
CHECK THIS OUT.
THAT IS AWESOME!
OH, YOU'RE GONNA PUT THAT
ON WINGS?
SEASON THEM
WITH A LITTLE KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
TOSS THEM IN THE SAUCE.
NICE--THICKENED UP
A LITTLE.
AND YOU DON'T SERVE 'EM LIKE
THAT? YOU PUT 'EM ON THE GRILL?
NOW WE'RE GONNA ACTUALLY
PUT THEM ON THE GRILL--
A LITTLE MORE FLAVOR, PUT THEM
RIGHT BACK IN THIS BOWL,
RE-TOSS 'EM, AND TAKE THEM
OVER HERE AND PLATE THEM
WITH A LITTLE
AVOCADO RANCH DRESSING.
HERE WE GO.
MMM. GOSH, DUDE.
MMM. THESE ARE ROCKIN'.
THE SAUCE IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
RIGHT HEAT, RIGHT SPICE.
MMM. MMM-MM-MMM!
DUDE, YOU ARE TRULY A ROCK STAR
ON THIS.
NICE JOB.
THANKS, MAN.
GOTTA COME TRY
THESE WINGS.
ADOBO WINGS.
FANTASTIC.
CARAMELIZED ON THE OUTSIDE
WHEN IT'S GRILLED
PUTS IT OVER THE TOP.
PORK MOLE PLATTER.
FRESH FOOD, UNIQUE FOOD--
AMAZING.
(Brian) ADOBO MAC-AND-CHEESE,
PLEASE.
YOU'RE KNOCKING THIS FOOD OUT.
IT'S A GREAT JOB.
THANKS, MAN.
I APPRECIATE IT.
REALLY A PLEASURE, BRO.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
PICK IT UP.
WE'RE HEADING TO IDAHO...
EVERYTHING TASTES FRESH
AND HOMEMADE.
FOR CHICKEN PIZZA...
IS YOUR MOUTH WATERING?
AND BURGERS...
THIS IS BEER.
BAKED IN BEER.
MMM! DUDE!
NOW THERE'S PLACES
ALL AROUND THIS COUNTRY THAT
WE'VE HEARD ABOUT BUT HAVEN'T
HAD A CHANCE TO VISIT.
NOW I'VE ALWAYS HEARD ABOUT
COEUR d'ALENE, IDAHO,
AND ITS BEAUTIFUL LAKE,
AND NOW I'M FINALLY HERE
TO CHECK OUT
A MOM-AND-POP PIZZA JOINT
WITH A REAL-DEAL ITALIAN NAME
AND THE COOKIN' TO BACK IT UP.
THIS IS CAPONE'S PUB & GRILL.
BOTH THOSE PIES
ARE READY.
MY IRISH AUNT
TAUGHT MY SICILIAN DAD
HOW TO COOK ITALIAN FOOD,
AND, UH, HE TAUGHT ME.
PICK IT UP.
SO WHEN TOM CAPONE...
DID YOU GET SOMETHING
TO EAT?
AND HIS WIFE TERESA
BOUGHT THIS BAR 19 YEARS AGO,
THERE WAS NO QUESTION
WHAT THE MENU WOULD BE.
MEATBALL!
EVERYTHING TASTES FRESH
AND HOMEMADE.
PIZZA.
THE BEST PIE THAT I'VE HAD--
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
THE CRUST IS GREAT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING FIRST?
PIZZA DOUGH.
FLOUR, ACTIVE DRY YEAST,
SALT...
SUGAR'S WHAT THE YEAST
NEEDS.
RIGHT. BROWN SUGAR.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
MIX IT UP.
ADD OUR WATER.
WE'LL LET THAT MIX FOR A MINUTE
BEFORE WE ADD THE OIL.
WE USE A GARLIC-INFUSED OIL.
I'LL ROAST MY GARLIC
IN THIS OIL.
I LOVE IT.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
GO STRAIGHT FROM THIS.
GONNA BENCH IT,
LET IT REST
FOR TEN MINUTES.
OKAY.
FOLD IT
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
JUST TO GET
SOME OF THAT FLOUR
SO IT'S NOT SO--RIGHT.
GET THAT AIR OUT OF IT.
WE PORTION IT OUT
TO 24 OUNCES EACH.
OKAY, SO WE ROLL THEM
INTO THEMSELVES
AND SEAL OFF THE BOTTOMS.
THAT'S IT.
PUT IT INTO PROOFING BOXES
FOR THREE DAYS
UNTIL WE'RE GONNA USE THEM.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME PIZZA SAUCE.
TOMATO FILLETS,
GROUND TOMATOES HERE.
I GOT YOU. I CAN
SEE YOU FROM HERE.
DRIED PARSLEY,
DRIED BASIL.
AND WE'RE NOT
GONNA COOK THIS?
THIS IS A NON-COOK SAUCE.
REALLY?
DRIED OREGANO--
IT'S GONNA COOK A LITTLE
WHEN IT'S ON TOP
OF THE PIZZAS.
DIG THAT.
YEAH. BROWN SUGAR. THIS IS
THAT GARLIC-INFUSED OIL.
NOW WE GRIND IT UP.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
SOME SAFETY GOGGLES ON!
NAH!
GOOD TO GO.
IT'S GONNA BE A GOOD PIE.
I HOPE SO.
WITH A NAME LIKE CAPONE,
IT BETTER BE.
BETTER BE.
OKAY.
THE PIZZAS ARE GREAT.
IT'S GOT CRUST AND THE SAUCE
AND THE FRESH INGREDIENTS.
IT'S ALWAYS GOT
TONS OF TOPPINGS.
LIKE THE HEART BLOCKER
WITH PEPPERONI,
SALAMI, AND SAUSAGE...
PICK IT UP!
THE TACO,
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
ROASTED GARLIC CHICKEN PIZZA.
DEFINITELY TASTE
THE GARLIC--VERY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT, MAN,
HOW WE GONNA MAKE THAT?
WE TAKE THE CHICKEN BREASTS
AND TRIM THEM UP.
BRINE THE CHICKEN.
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR.
SUGAR, SALT, AND WATER.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
KOSHER SALT,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
GARLIC SALT,
WHAT WE CALL TOM'S SALT.
OKAY.
GOES ON OUR CHICKEN.
COOK IT OFF IN THE OVEN--
450, 20 MINUTES.
CHOP IT UP.
ALL RIGHT, PIZZA TIME.
THIS IS SEMOLINA.
THIS IS
A 24-OUNCE DOUGH BALL.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA STRETCH IT.
OKAY, READY? GO.
READY.
OH, I LIKE THIS.
TUCK THIS UP UNDER
TO CREATE THAT CRUST.
TOMATO SAUCE WE MADE.
AND THIS IS
A WHOLE MILK MOZZARELLA.
ARTICHOKE HEARTS,
ROASTED GARLIC,
KALAMATA OLIVES,
AND SUN-DRIED TOMATOES.
GET IT GOING.
AND IT BAKES ON THAT?
HALFWAY--SLIDE IT OFF
AND GET THAT GOOD CRISP BOTTOM.
NOW WHAT?
MAKE GARLIC BUTTER--
WHIPPED MARGARINE,
FRESH GARLIC, MOZZARELLA...
DRIED PARSLEY.
CHEDDAR, JACK,
PECORINO ROMANO.
MIX IT UP. TAKE THE CHICKEN
AND HEAT IT UP ON THE GRILL
A LITTLE BIT
WITH SOME GARLIC BUTTER.
THIS IS WHERE YOU'LL GET
YOUR GARLIC FLAVOR.
DIG THAT.
PIZZA READY.
COMING RIGHT BEHIND YOU.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
CUT IT UP. WE'RE GONNA TOP
THE PIZZA WITH THE CHICKEN.
IS YOUR MOUTH WATERING?
THAT'S THE ROASTED GARLIC
CHICKEN PIZZA.
MMM.
THIS ROCKS, MAN. EXCELLENT.
THAT'S GREAT DOUGH. MMM.
AND THE CHICKEN WITH THE GARLIC
BUTTER REALLY STANDS OUT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE PUTTING
THE ICING ON TOP.
GARLIC CHICKEN--THE NEW
ICING IN FLAVOR TOWN.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
TRY A BITE OF THAT. MMM!
(woman)
ROASTED GARLIC CHICKEN PIZZA.
LOVE ALL THE DIFFERENT FLAVORS
THAT ARE ON IT.
IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
THERE'S NO SHORTAGE
OF GARLIC,
AND THE CRUST
DOES SET IT APART.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE
TO COME.
HOW'S THE PIE TONIGHT?
JUST KIND OF A LOCAL HANGOUT.
THE KIND OF PLACE
TOM WOULD HAND OUT.
THIS ISN'T JUST SOMEBODY
TRYING TO DECORATE A RESTAURANT.
THIS IS REALLY YOUR STUFF.
IT'S MY SOUL.
MEMORABILIA FROM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
EVERYTHING FROM THE MITTS
TO THE POSTERS.
THE DIFFERENT SIGNS
AND PICTURES.
LIKE THIS ONE OF DON LARSEN,
THE ONLY DUDE
TO PITCH A PERFECT GAME
IN THE WORLD SERIES.
AND TODAY, WE'VE GOT MORE
THAN A PICTURE.
DON LARSEN.
HERE WITH HIS GRANDSON CODY
AND HIS WIFE CORRINE.
YOU GUYS BEEN COMING HERE
A WHILE?
16 YEARS.
HOW DOES THIS FOOD STACK UP
IN ALL YOUR TRAVELS?
EXCELLENT.
TOM HAS A GREAT BREAD,
AND I THINK BREAD
MAKES THE BEST SANDWICHES.
WHEN YOU OPENED THIS JOINT,
DID YOU THINK
YOU WERE GONNA BE A BAKER?
NO.
BUT HE IS NOW, DOING ROLLS
FOR ALL THE SUBS.
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
MMM.
WHEN YOU BAKE YOUR OWN BREAD,
THAT'S THE PERFECT BEGINNING.
AND GET THIS...
CHEESEBURGER.
HE'S EVEN CRANKIN' OUT
HIS OWN HAMBURGER BUNS.
CRUSTY TOP, REALLY FRESH,
VERY DELICIOUS.
NOW WHAT ARE WE ON?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE BURGER BUNS.
THIS IS THE STARTER--
7 POUNDS OF WATER,
A PINCH OF YEAST,
7 POUNDS OF FLOUR.
YOU'RE JUST BUILDING THIS
IN 5-GALLON BUCKETS.
YOU HAVE IT AS YOU NEED IT,
AND THIS IS THE BASIS
FOR MAKING THE BUNS.
CORRECT. NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD FLOUR, SALT, BROWN SUGAR.
MORE YEAST.
SOFTENED BUTTER.
MIX IT UP.
YEAH.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF WATER?
8 1/2 POUNDS.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THIS.
THAT STARTER, MAN.
OHH!
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT. THAT'S
WHAT GIVES IT ALL ITS FLAVOR.
OKAY, SO LET THIS GO
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
IT'S ALL GONNA PULL AWAY,
AND IT'S FINISHED.
WE'RE GONNA BENCH IT
AN HOUR.
THIS IS GONNA PROOF UP.
NEXT, WE'RE GONNA FOLD IT.
NOW PORTION OUT OUR
BURGER BUNS TO 4 1/2 OUNCES.
THROW THEM IN THE MACHINE.
THIS DOES THE WORK FOR YOU?
SURE DOES.
NICE!
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS REST
ABOUT AN HOUR.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA TAKE IT
AND PRESS IT INTO HERE.
WE'LL THROW IT IN THE PROOFER
45 MINUTES.
PROOFS UP. EGG WASH.
SESAME SEEDS.
WE'LL BAKE IT AT WHAT?
425 FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
(whistles)
SO THERE'S OUR BEAUTY BUN.
MMM. IT STILL SMELLS GREAT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
ULTIMATE CHEESEBURGER.
A LITTLE BUTTER ON HERE.
LET THAT TOAST UP.
BURGER ON THE GRILL,
A LITTLE BIT OF TOM SALT.
NOW GIVE IT A FLIP.
THIS IS BEER.
BEER?
STEAMING THE BURGER
IN BEER.
NICE!
GONNA PULL THE BUN.
NOW THE CHEESE--THIS
IS THE MOZZ, THE JACK...
PECORINO ROMANO...
CHEDDAR.
PUT A LITTLE PROVOLONE,
MOUND THAT UP,
AND THEN IT'S DONE.
TAKE A LOOKY-LOO.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM! DUDE!
THAT BUN IS OFF THE HOOK.
IF YOU'RE GONNA EAT A BURGER,
YOU SHOULD EAT AT A PLACE
THAT MAKES THEIR OWN BUN.
REMEMBER HOW WHEN
WE WERE MAKING THE DOUGH,
I COULD SMELL ALL THAT YEAST?
IT COMES THROUGH IN THE FLAVOR.
FOR A PIZZA JOINT TO PUT THAT
KIND OF CARE INTO A BURGER--
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
ULTIMATE CHEESEBURGER.
LOTS OF CHEESE.
THE BREAD'S NICE AND SOFT.
IT TASTES REALLY GOOD
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
PASTRAMI.
IT'S JUST GREAT FOOD.
YOU SHOULD BE A DEEJAY.
AND YOUR LAST NAME
IS REALLY CAPONE.
IT IS.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY.
SERIOUS.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
WE HAD A BLAST.
THANK YOU.
CONGRATS. (clicks tongue)
APPRECIATE IT.
NEXT STOP...
IT'S ONE
OF THE BEST-KEPT SECRETS.
NASHVILLE.
I'M GONNA GO SPICY JERK.
GOOD CHOICE.
FOR FAST FOOD...
MANGO CHUTNEY FRIED CHICKEN.
THE JAMAICAN WAY.
HUGE FLAVOR.
EXCELLENT. WOW.
WHEN YOU'RE IN NASHVILLE,
YOU CAN TAKE A SHORT WALK
OR A SHUTTLE
NORTH OF THE DOWNTOWN AREA
TO THIS PLACE,
NASHVILLE FARMERS' MARKET.
OH, THEY'VE GOT EVERYTHING
YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND--
ALL THE FRUIT
AND VEGETABLE STANDS,
AND THEN THEY'VE GOT
THE FLEA MARKETS
ON THE WEEKENDS,
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
WHAT YOU'D EXPECT--
A JAMAICAN RESTAURANT.
THIS IS JAMAICAWAY.
CURRY GOAT. WHAT ELSE
WOULD YOU LIKE?
DID YOU SAY
COLLARD GREENS?
SPICY JERK CHICKEN.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
I'M A BIG FAN
OF THE GOAT CURRY.
SO THIS IS REAL JAMAICAN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE SAME FAVORITES
OUIDA KUHLOKOH-BRADSHAW
GREW UP EATING...
WHITE MEAT OR DARK MEAT?
IN JAMAICA.
SWEET POTATOES
AND PINEAPPLE.
AND WHEN SHE CAME
TO THE STATES...
AFTER SCHOOL,
I USED TO COME HOME
EVERY AFTERNOON
TO COOK FOR EVERYBODY.
TILAPIA ESCOVEITCH.
AND I HAVE NINE SIBLINGS.
THEN AFTER
22 YEARS OF TEACHING...
I DECIDED TO DO WHAT
I WAS PASSIONATE ABOUT.
SO SHE PACKED AWAY THE BOOKS,
CASHED IN HER SAVINGS...
HOW ARE YOU TODAY, MA'AM?
AND OPENED THIS JOINT.
LEGIT?
REAL FOR DEAL, MAN.
MANGO CHUTNEY FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S BATTER-FRIED,
AND IT'S GOT LIKE A CHUTNEY
MANGO-TYPE SAUCE ON IT--MMM.
I KNOW
THIS CAST OF CHARACTERS.
WE'RE MAKING MANGO CHUTNEY SAUCE
FOR OUR FRIED CHICKEN.
OKAY.
GREEN PEPPERS, RED PEPPERS,
YELLOW PEPPERS, ONIONS,
REDUCED MANGOES.
AND YOU MAKE
THE REDUCED MANGO?
YES, WE DO.
WATER AND MANGOES.
AND A LITTLE SUGAR. AND NOW
WE ADD IN SOME MANGO PURéE.
OOH.
YOU'RE TALKING JAMAICAN FOOD--
SCOTCH BONNETS.
THAT GOES HAND IN HAND.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NEXT, I'M GONNA PURéE IT.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE
SOME CHUNK TO IT.
YEP.
A LITTLE BIT OF KICK TO IT...
MM-HMM.
SOME OF THE FRESH
PEPPER FLAVOR...
MM-HMM.
AND THEN THE SWEETNESS
OF THE MANGO,
AND THAT'S GONNA
GO ON FRIED CHICKEN.
YEP.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO SEE THIS FRIED CHICKEN.
WE'RE GONNA CUT
OUR CHICKEN.
BONELESS, SKINLESS.
MM-HMM.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A MARINADE FOR THIS?
A MARINADE FOR IT.
SEASONING SALT,
COARSE BLACK PEPPER,
SOME PAPRIKA. NOW I'M GONNA
MIX IT TOGETHER.
SO THIS IS DONE.
NOW WE GO MAKE THE WET BATTER
AND THE DRY BATTER AND WE'LL
BE READY TO FRY 'EM.
THE WET BATTER HAS FLOUR,
BREADCRUMBS,
A LITTLE BIT MORE BLACK PEPPER,
SEASONING SALT,
PAPRIKA, AND SOME WATER.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA WHISK IT TOGETHER.
OKAY. AND THE DRY?
IT'S THE SAME EXACT THING.
JUST WITHOUT THE WET.
YES.
AND THEN WE'LL GET
INTO BREADING IT.
THAT'S CORRECT.
GOT IT.
I WANT TO TAKE MY CHICKEN,
PUT THIS IN THE WET BATTER,
AND YOU--
THAT BATTER IS THICK.
THINK ABOUT PANCAKE BATTER
GONE THICKER.
INTO MY DRY BATTER.
AND YOU PAN-FRY THESE?
YEAH, WE PAN-FRY IT.
THAT IS SOME
CRISPY CRUNCHY ON THERE.
HOW MANY DO YOU
NORMALLY PUT ON A PLATE?
THREE.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
MANGO CHUTNEY SAUCE TO IT.
JUST RIGHT ON TOP.
LOOK AT THOSE COLORS ON THAT.
LOOK AT THAT CHICKEN.
LOOK AT THE CRISPY CRUNCHY
ON THAT.
(crunches)
FIRST, I'M GONNA TELL YOU THAT
THE CRUNCH ON THIS THING
IS "CRUNCHINTACIOUS."
(crunching)
WHEN YOU GO
TO FLAVOR TOWN PHONE COMPANY
AND YOU GET THAT
CRUNCH RING-BACK TONE,
THAT'S WHAT IT SOUNDS LIKE.
LISTEN.
(crunching)
THE CHICKEN'S TENDER,
BUT IT'S GOT GREAT SEASONING
UNDERNEATH IT.
HUGE FLAVOR
WITH THE MANGO CHUTNEY,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE HEAT
FROM THE SCOTCH BONNET.
IF YOU LIKE FRIED CHICKEN,
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
MANGO CHUTNEY FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S JUICY.
I JUST LOVE THE COMBINATION
OF THE CRUNCH
AND THE SWEETNESS
FROM THE MANGO--MMM.
THEY ACTUALLY USE REAL FRUIT,
WHICH IS VERY GOOD.
HERE'S THE OXTAIL.
SHE DOES EVERYTHING
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
AND SHE DOES IT
FAST ENOUGH...
RICE-N-PEAS...
BARBECUE BEEF.
TO CRANK OUT A THOUSAND MEALS
A WEEK FOR THE LUNCH CROWD.
PLANTAINS, PLEASE.
WOULD YOU LIKE CORNBREAD?
AND COLLARDS.
THANK YOU.
YOU CAN GET IN AND OUT
REALLY QUICK.
AND STILL GET THE REAL DEAL.
WHAT ARE YOU ENJOYING?
OXTAIL. MMM.
IT'S TREMENDOUS.
CAN I HAVE
THE ACKEE AND SALTFISH?
MY FAVORITE FOOD--
ACKEE AND SALTFISH.
ACKEE? YEAH.
THAT'S A YELLOW JAMAICAN FRUIT.
IT KIND OF LIKE
HAS AN ARTICHOKE TASTE.
AND WHEN YOU PAIR IT
WITH SALTFISH...
IT IS NATIONAL DISH
OF JAMAICA.
ACKEE AND SALTFISH.
THAT BRINGS US
TO SALTED COD.
MM-HMM.
GIVE US THE DE-SALTING.
WE'RE GONNA POUR
SOME HOT, HOT WATER.
PULL OUT SOME OF THE SALT,
AND HOW LONG WILL THIS SIT
HERE AND, UH...
ABOUT TWO HOURS.
SO HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHEN IT'S READY?
'CAUSE IT'S FALLING
EASILY APART.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
NOW IS TAKE IT OUT OF THE WATER
AND CRUMBLE IT?
YEAH.
SO THIS IS ALL READY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA COOK IT UP?
YES, SIR.
SUNSHINE, I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO SAY THIS TO YOU,
BUT THE ACKEE
LOOKS LIKE EGG-EE.
IT'S NOT.
THE FIRST THING
I'M GONNA DO
IS I'M GONNA HAVE
A NICE HOT SKILLET...
OKAY.
AND I'M GONNA ADD
SOME COOKING OIL TO IT.
ADD GARLIC. THIS IS THYME.
JAMAICAN THYME. WHOA!
I WASN'T HIDING BEHIND HER.
YES, YOU WERE.
I WAS JUST MAKING SURE I HAD
HER PERSPECTIVE ON IT.
SHREDDED ONION.
ONION.
THYME IS JUST COMING OUT
BIG-TIME.
GREEN PEPPERS,
YELLOW BELL PEPPERS,
RED PEPPERS,
SOME GREEN ONIONS,
STIR IT ALL IN.
WHAT I'M GONNA DO NOW
IS TO ADD MY CODFISH,
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
PAPRIKA, AND THEN ACKEE.
ACKEE, THE EGG FRUIT.
ACKEE.
LOOK.
IT LOOKS INTERESTING.
BON APPéTIT.
IT'S THE ATTACK-EE
OF THE ACKEE.
MMM.
IT'S A VERY PLEASANT TEXTURE.
I MEAN, IT'S VERY SOFT
AND SILKY.
YOU GET THE TANGY, BRINY,
AND SALTINESS
OF THE FISH--MMM--
ALL THAT GREAT
VEGETABLE FLAVOR,
SLAM IT WITH SOME THYME,
I SEE HOW
IT ALL COMES TOGETHER.
NOW WHAT I'M EXCITED TO DO
IS GO TO JAMAICAN
AND TRY THEIR VERSION.
(laughs) OKAY.
I KNOW
SHE MAKES IT THE BEST.
ACKEE AND SALTFISH.
JUST TONS OF FLAVOR
GOING ON HERE.
IT'S SPICY, THE WAY I LIKE IT.
IT'S VERY NICE.
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
HOW DOES THIS STACK UP?
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
FROM THE CLASSICS
YOU'D EXPECT...
SPICY JERK CHICKEN.
TO SOME THINGS MOST FOLKS
HAVE NEVER EVEN HEARD OF...
YOU EVER HAD
COCONUT DROPS?
COCONUT GINGER
PEANUT BRITTLE.
MMM. ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
IT'S NUTS.
CURRY GOAT, MA'AM?
AT JAMAICAWAY
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE...
RICE-N-PEAS WITH THAT.
FOLKS ARE LINING UP
FOR REAL-DEAL JAMAICAN...
GOOD CHOICE.
'CAUSE OUIDA KUHLOKOH-BRADSHAW
IS CHOPPING,
FRYING,
AND HAMMERING OUT RECIPES
SHE'S BEEN MAKING
ALL HER LIFE.
I'M GONNA GO SPICY JERK--
DEFINITELY MY FAVORITE.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD
COCONUT DROPS?
THOSE ARE A JAMAICAN SNACK
MADE FROM WHOLE COCONUT.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES. MMM.
I GREW UP EATING THIS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
UH, COCONUT TIME.
FIRST OF ALL, WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE WATER OUT OF THE COCONUT.
SO NOW...
I'M GONNA BREAK MY COCONUT,
SO WHAT I DO,
I HOLD A TOWEL AROUND IT.
OKAY.
IT'S EASIER, AND THEN
I SMASH IT. SEE?
AND NOW MY COCONUT
IS ALL SMASHED.
SO HOW DO WE GET THE SKIN
OFF OF IT?
ALL YOU NEED TO DO IS A SHARP
KNIFE AND GO LIKE THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS AN EXCELLENT COCONUT,
BY THE WAY.
IT DOESN'T TASTE
LIKE THE COCONUT
THAT COMES OUT
OF THE PACKAGE.
IT TASTES FRESH.
OH, YEAH. TASTES JUST LIKE
SUNTAN LOTION.
(laughs)
OKAY, SO WE CHOP ALL THIS UP.
THEN WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
WE'RE GONNA BOIL IT.
SO THE FIRST THING WE DO
IS TO TAKE SOME WATER.
OKAY.
HERE'S A SKILLET. WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME CUBED COCONUT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BROWN SUGAR.
WHOA! A LOT.
AND THEN WE HAVE
SOME CUBED GINGER,
AND I'M GONNA JUST
STIR EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
SO YOU JUST LET THIS SIT HERE
AND CARAMELIZE AND REDUCE...
UH-HUH.
UNTIL IT JUST KIND OF MAKES IT
LIKE A STICKY PASTE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO I THINK
IT'S READY TO DROP.
DROP THEM ON A SHEET PAN.
IT'S LIKE JAMAICAN
PEANUT BRITTLE,
EXCEPT IT HAS COCONUT
AND GINGER, YEAH.
I LOVE GINGER.
SO THAT'S ALL GONNA STICK
TOGETHER?
YES.
AND LET THEM COOL.
IT TAKES ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
AND YOU TAKE IT OFF
AND EAT IT.
HOW DO YOU EAT IT?
JUST BITE INTO IT
OR YOU CAN BREAK A PIECE OFF.
THAT'S NUTS. COCONUT GINGER
PEANUT BRITTLE.
COCONUT DROPS.
BRITTLE.
IT'S CARAMELIZED
GINGER CANDY
WITH... THE COCONUT...
REALLY WORKING
AS THE TEXTURE.
I LIKE THINGS WITH CHEW.
AH, THIS IS SOME
OF THE BEST...
BRITTLE DROP
I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S A COCONUT DROP,
JAMAICAN SNACK.
BRITTLE DROP.
COCONUT DROPS.
OKAY, THANKS FOR COMING
TO TRIPLE "D." BRITTLE.
COCONUT DROPS.
WHENEVER I COME HERE,
I USUALLY GET THIS.
COCONUT GINGER--THIS IS WHAT
YOU CALL DIGGING IN.
MMM.
SO ONCE I FOUND THIS PLACE,
THAT WAS IT.
IT'S ONE THE BEST-KEPT SECRETS
IN NASHVILLE, ACTUALLY.
BARBECUE BEEF.
I'M GOING TO JAMAICA.
THAT'S IT.
CURRY CHICKEN. OKAY.
YOU'RE AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
I'M COMING BACK.
YOU ARE?
I WANT SOME OF THAT, UH,
THAT COCONUT BRITTLE.
(laughs)
LIKE WE ALWAYS SAY,
IF IT'S FUNKY, WE'LL FIND IT.
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
THESE RECIPES,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO YOU GET
THAT REALLY NICE--
CLANK!
DID YOU JUST FEEL
THE EARTH QUAKE?
BONK! YOU'RE LUCKY YOU
DIDN'T KNOCK YOUR TEETH OUT.