HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MY FATHER MADE
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
FAMILY JOINTS.
CAN I HELP
WHO'S NEXT THEN?
IN KANSAS CITY...
GOT TWO FLANKS
COMIN' UP.
WHERE A HUSBAND
AND WIFE TEAM...
GOT A STEAK...
ARE SERVING UP SOUP
AND SANDWICHES...
YOU CAN TASTE HOW MUCH
THEY LOVE FOOD HERE.
THEIR WAY.
POSOLES FOR YOU.
KNOCKOUT. MMM.
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
IT'S JUST GOOD
HOME COOKING.
THE THIRD GENERATION JOINT...
CABBAGE ROLL WITH A SIDE
OF SAUERKRAUT.
SCRATCH-MAKING A TASTE...
MMM.
OF THE OLD COUNTRY...
THE BEST EASTERN EUROPEAN
FOOD THAT YOU CAN FIND.
AND CRANKING OUT
SOME SERIOUS SAUSAGE.
WHEEL THAT RIGHT UP
TO THE '67.
AND IN WEST VIRGINIA...
LOOK AT THIS PLACE!
WE FOLLOW A COUPLE...
DINNER BELL
FOR JANE AND ROGER!
TO THEIR 100th STOP...
WE WANTED TO SPELL OUT
"100."
ON THEIR ULTIMATE
"TRIPLE D" ROAD TRIP.
WOW, 100 LOCATIONS?
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP
RIGHT HERE ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN
KANSAS CITY, MISSOURI,
IN AN AREA KNOWN
AS COLUMBUS PARK--
IT'S KIND OF ON THE NORTHEAST
SIDE OF TOWN--
TO VISIT A JOINT
THAT FOR 40 YEARS
WAS AN OLD-SCHOOL
SUNDRY SHOP.
NOW IT'S HOME TO A BREAKFAST
AND SANDWICH SHOP
THAT IS ANYTHING
BUT OLD-SCHOOL.
FROM WHAT I HEAR,
THIS HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
ARE SERVING UP
SOUP AND SANDWICHES
THAT ARE UNIQUE, HANDMADE,
AND ANYTHING BUT ORDINARY.
THIS IS HAPPY GILLIS
CAFé AND HANGOUT.
I GOT A MEAT LOAF
AND A BUTTERNUT SQUASH.
PEOPLE THINK
SOUP AND SANDWICHES,
RUN OF THE MILL,
EVERYDAY THING, BUT NOT HERE.
GOT TWO FLANKS
COMIN' UP.
PHENOMENAL.
THE COMBINATIONS--INCREDIBLE.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
TOP-QUALITY FOOD,
FULL OF FLAVOR.
WE LIKE TO COME HERE
FOR BREAKFAST.
GILLIS BREAKFAST
SANDWICH.
JUST SIMPLE, FRESH,
USING LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
A VIRTUAL OBSESSION
FOR TODD SHULTE...
GOT A STEAK.
AND HIS WIFE
TRACY ZINN...
YOU HAD THE CLUB.
YOU CAN TASTE HOW MUCH
THEY LOVE FOOD HERE.
ONE SEARED TUNA.
HE IS AMAZING AT PUTTING
THE RIGHT THINGS TOGETHER.
AND A FLANK STEAK.
MARINATED FLANK STEAK.
THE COMBINATION OF FLAVORS
ARE ALWAYS UNEXPECTED.
COCA-COLA WITH RED WINE ON FLANK
STEAK. THIS'LL BE INTERESTING.
SHOULD BE.
OLIVE OIL.
AND WHO TAUGHT YOU
THIS RECIPE?
WELL, I KIND OF
MADE IT UP MYSELF.
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER.
AND DID YOU
FRESH CRACK THAT?
FRESH THIS MORNING.
THAT'S THE WAY TO DO IT
IF YOU REALLY WANT TO GET
THE GREAT PEPPER FLAVOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
THAT WAS A LITTLE.
WE DON'T WANT IT
TO DRAW OUT.
GIVE A SPLASH OF THE RED WINE
AND A LITTLE BIT OF COCA-COLA.
IS THAT A KANSAS CITY THING
THAT I'VE JUST BEEN MISSING?
NO,
SOMEBODY TAUGHT THIS TO ME
WHEN I WAS DOWN IN ST. THOMAS.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
TO THE REFRIGERATOR,
LET IT MARINATE
FOR A COUPLE DAYS.
DIG IT.
WE'LL GET A LITTLE
CANOLA IN THERE.
OUR FLANK STEAKS' BEEN
MARINATING FOR TWO DAYS.
WE'LL MAKE SURE THAT
WE'RE PATTING IT DRY
SO THERE'S NOT
EXCESS MOISTURE.
SO WE'RE NOT BOILING--
GIVE IT A GOOD SEAR.
KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE FRESH CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
PAN'S GETTING NICE AND HOT.
WE JUST LET IT GO.
WE'RE GONNA FLIP IT.
OH, THAT LOOKS GREAT.
THAT'S A NICE SEAR.
BRINGING THEM OUT.
NOW WE'RE ON TO THE NEXT STEP.
ALL THE AROMATICS.
ONIONS, CARROTS.
SOME REAL NICE SWEETNESS
COMING OUT OF THAT.
WE DON'T WANT 'EM
TO COOK DOWN TOO MUCH,
'CAUSE THEY ARE GONNA SPEND
SOME TIME IN THE OVEN.
GARLIC.
GET THAT INCORPORATED.
A BIT MORE SALT IN THERE.
THAT'LL HELP SWEAT 'EM
A LITTLE MORE.
BLACK PEPPER.
BEFORE THAT GARLIC BURNS.
WE'RE GONNA GO
RED WINE FIRST...
THAT'S AWESOME.
SOME FRESH HERBS.
BASIL.
A LITTLE BASIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF TARRAGON.
PARSLEY.
LOVE USING
FRESH PARSLEY.
COCA-COLA.
ABOUT 6 OUNCES OF SODA.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF SPRITE.
YOU AND YOUR SODAS, MAN.
BRING THE FLANK STEAK
BACK INTO THE PAN,
POP A LID ON IT,
THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
AT WHAT TEMP?
325. WE'LL BE GOOD TO GO
IN ABOUT 2 1/2, 3 HOURS.
THIS IS ALL
FOR A SANDWICH.
GREAT, 'CAUSE YOU GET ROUND
HEAT, ALL THE WAY AROUND.
ABSOLUTELY.
WE'LL REMOVE IT,
LET IT COOL, AND WE'LL SHRED IT.
JUST GONNA BE FALL APART
TENDER. OKAY.
PUT IT TOGETHER.
A LITTLE TOAST ON THAT.
MMM, CAN'T BEAT THAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF HORSERADISH
SAUCE THAT WE MAKE.
FRESH ARUGULA
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL,
SOME OF OUR NICE
PICKLED RED ONIONS.
THERE'S OUR
SHREDDED FLANK.
SHREDDED FLANK,
JUST A TOUCH MORE SEASONING.
SALT, CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
AND THAT'S HOW SHE ROLLS.
THERE'S THE SANDWICH.
GIVE IT A GOOD CUT.
MMM.
THE BEEF ITSELF IS FLAVOR 101.
MMM. KILLER. YOU DON'T SEE
FLANK STEAK IN LONG SANDWICHES.
THEN YOU PUT IT WITH
JUST SIMPLE SUBTLETIES
LIKE A PICKLED
RED ONION.
THE HORSERADISH CREAM--MMM.
THAT SANDWICH IS ROCK STAR.
THANKS.
SERIOUSLY.
I GOT A STEAK SANDWICH
FOR THE BAR.
IT'S JUICY,
IT'S FLAVORFUL.
VERY SAVORY, WONDERFUL.
IT'S A GOOD VARIETY
OF SANDWICHES.
THE B.L.T.
IT'S ALWAYS, LIKE,
MADE PERFECTLY.
HE CAN PUT
TOGETHER THINGS
THAT YOU JUST DON'T
FIND ANYWHERE ELSE.
UNLESS YOU GO TO SPAIN...
TRACY, I GOT A BOCADILLO.
WITH FRESH CHILIES,
GROUND BEEF, AND PORK...
DELICIOUS.
OR MEXICO...
ONE TORTA.
WITH A HOMEMADE BEAN SALSA
AND SHREDDED CHICKEN.
JUST OUTSTANDING.
AND EVEN VIETNAM.
I WOULD LIKE
BANH MI, PLEASE.
TODD'S TWIST ON VIETNAMESE
STREET FOOD.
THE BANH MI SANDWICH--
PHENOMENAL.
EVERY BITE
IS PERFECT.
HANDMADE MEATBALLS,
TWICE COOKED, PICKLED VEGGIES,
LOCAL BREAD, SPICY HOISIN.
OH, GREAT CRUNCH,
TEXTURE--PERFECT.
DUDE, YOU ARE SO OUTSIDE
OF THE BOX. NICE JOB.
FULL BANH MI.
THE BEST.
POSOLE MEAT LOAF,
POSOLE BANH MI.
HE TURNS THE ORDINARY
INTO--
INTO EXTRAORDINARY.
YES.
ALL RIGHT.
EVERY SANDWICH,
EVERY SOUP.
WE ORIGINALLY STARTED OUT
WITH A SOUP BUSINESS.
THIS IS THEN
THE EXTENSION OF THAT.
A COUPLE POSOLES
FOR YOU.
WHAT'S YOUR
FAVORITE SOUP?
THE SQUASH.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE HAD
SQUASH SOUP.
COME ON!
LOOK AT ME LIKE
I'M FROM A DIFFERENT PLANET.
ALL THE SOUPS HERE
ARE FANTASTIC.
TWO POSOLE FOR TABLE SIX.
POSOLE VERDE--INCREDIBLE.
CLASSIC GREEN CHILI
CHICKEN SOUP FROM MEXICO.
A LITTLE BIT OF CANOLA
TO THE PAN, GET IT HOT.
ADD OUR ONIONS.
COAT OF SOME OIL
ON THOSE.
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
OH, GO ALL IN.
ALL RIGHT, GET THAT GOING,
GET A LITTLE TOAST ON IT.
GROUND TOASTED CUMIN,
DONE FROM THE WHOLE FORM.
TOASTED ANISE.
I THINK THAT'S INTERESTING THAT
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE USING.
IT GIVES IT JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF A BACKBONE
SO IT KIND OF
BRINGS IT OUT.
A LITTLE TANG.
AND OREGANO. LET THE OIL
KIND OF BRING OUT THEIR OILS.
SMELL 'EM
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
SO IN WITH THE CHICKEN.
WE'RE NOT ONLY FORTIFYING IT
WITH FLAVOR,
WE'RE ALSO GETTING
THE CHICKEN TO A POINT
WHERE WE CAN SHRED IT
TO PUT IT IN THE SOUP.
YOU GOT IT.
A LITTLE SALT, PEPPER, AND NOW
WE'RE IN WITH THE STOCK.
SMELLS SO GOOD.
SOMEONE SHOULD CALL
THE POSOLE POLICE.
WHILE THE CHICKEN'S COOKING,
WHAT DO WE DO NEXT?
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO MAKE
THE GREEN SLURRY.
MMM. GREEN SLURRY.
(whistles)
EVERYTHING THAT'S
GONNA MAKE IT GREEN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER TO THE BLENDER.
TOMATILLOS, ADD THOSE IN.
POBLANOS.
AND YOU ROASTED
AND SKINNED THOSE?
YES, I DID. SOME CILANTRO,
SOME ROMAINE LEAVES,
A LITTLE BIT OF CUMIN ON TOP,
PUMPKINSEEDS,
A FEW OF THE CHILIES,
NICE LITTLE SPICE.
SOME JALAPEÑO, A LITTLE BIT
OF TOASTED ANISE.
AND A BUNCH
OF THE OREGANO.
LOVE MEXICAN OREGANO.
WE'RE JUST GONNA...
GIVE THIS A LITTLE PULSE.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
AND YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE IT
KIND OF IN THE CHUNKY FORM?
YEAH.
DIG IT.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
LET'S TAKE THIS TO THE POT.
CHICKEN COOKED IN THERE,
PULL IT TO COOL IN.
WE'RE GONNA SHRED
THE CHICKEN,
AND THEN TOWARDS THE END
OF THE COOKING PROCESS,
WE'LL THROW IT
RIGHT BACK IN THE POT.
COUPLE MORE INGREDIENTS--
POTATOES, HOMINY--
THE BIG, GIANT CORN.
LOVE HOMINY,
ESPECIALLY IN POSOLE.
STEP AWAY FROM THE POT,
LET THE POTATOES,
THE HOMINY GETS GOING.
WE'LL ADD THE CHICKEN BACK IN,
FINISH IT WITH THE SLURRY.
WOW.
SO HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
ABOUT ANOTHER TEN MINUTES.
AND WHAT'S IT GONNA
BE SERVED WITH?
GARNISH IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF QUESO FRESCO,
AVOCADO, SLICED RADISH,
AND CHOPPED CILANTRO.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE, HUH?
YES, SIR.
MMM, NICE FLAVOR
IN THAT BROTH. MMM.
THE CHICKEN--SUPER TENDER.
HOMINY'S GOT NICE BITE TO IT.
IT'S A LIGHT BROTH,
BUT VERY FLAVORFUL.
GLAD YOU'RE ENJOYING IT.
MMM, I'D EAT IT ALL.
DISH THAT UP AGAIN.
I'D GO ROUND SIX AND SEVEN
WITH THAT ONE.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S A KNOCKOUT.
THE POSOLE
IS JUST AMAZING.
HI, GUYS,
HOW IS EVERYTHING?
THEY WANT TO GIVE THE CUSTOMER
SOMETHING THAT'S SPECTACULAR.
B.L.T.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD. I'VE HAD
ALMOST THE WHOLE MENU.
I LOVE THE PLACE.
THIS IS THE KIND
OF PLACE
YOU WANT TO HAVE
IN YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M NOT EVEN FROM THIS TOWN--
I WANT TO COME HERE
JUST TO COME AND HANG OUT.
GOT AN EXTRA COUCH?
WE'VE GOT AN APARTMENT
UPSTAIRS.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO MINNEAPOLIS...
SZEGEDIN GOULASH.
REAL WORKING MAN'S FOOD,
VERY HEARTY.
FOR A CULINARY WORKOUT.
BEAUTIFUL.
I'M HERE
IN NORTHEAST MINNEAPOLIS,
OR "NORDEAST,"
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT,
RIGHT ACROSS
THE HENNEPIN AVENUE BRIDGE,
IN AN AREA
THAT USED TO BE HOME
TO A LOT OF EASTERN
EUROPEAN FAMILIES,
SO OF COURSE YOU'D
EXPECT TO FIND WHAT?
EASTERN EUROPEAN RESTAURANT--
BUT HOW COOL IS IT
WHEN YOU FIND ONE
THAT'S MAKING IT ALL FROM
SCRATCH FOR THREE GENERATIONS?
THIS IS KRAMARCZUK'S.
SZEGEDIN GOULASH.
VERY EUROPEAN, I MEAN,
GENUINE EUROPEAN.
TOMATO CREAM SAUCE.
REAL WORKING MAN'S FOOD,
VERY HEARTY.
THREE MEAT,
THREE POTATO.
I'M HAVING VARENYKYS.
YOU'RE HAVING VARENYKYS?
YEAH.
OH, SO EASY
FOR YOU TO SAY.
SAUERKRAUT
AND HAM SOUP.
THE KIND OF MEAL THAT YOU WANT
TO GO RUN A CITY ON.
AND HE OUGHT TO KNOW...
I'M R.T. RYBAK.
I'M THE MAYOR OF MINNEAPOLIS.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO COME
AND GET A GREAT SAUSAGE.
HANDMADE.
ANYTHING ELSE TODAY?
LIKE THE ONES UKRAINIAN
IMMIGRANTS
WASYL KRAMARCZUK
AND HIS WIFE ANNA
STARTED MAKING
BACK IN '54.
WHEN HE STARTED THIS BUSINESS,
MY FATHER MADE
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
BEFORE IT WAS
THE COOL THING TO DO.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN OREST KRAMARCZUK...
HOW'S EVERYTHING?
ADDED THE CAFETERIA
IN '76...
SAUSAGE. THANK YOU.
WHERE HIS KIDS
NICK AND KATIE...
CAN I HELP
WHO'S NEXT THEN?
ARE ALREADY ON BOARD...
YOU'VE WORKED HERE
ALL YOUR LIFE?
PRETTY MUCH, YEP.
CRANKING OUT THE FAMILY RECIPES
SINCE SHE WAS 12.
GONNA MAKE SOME HALUBCY.
BOILED CABBAGE
IS HALUBCY?
BOILED CABBAGE ROLLS.
SALTED WATER WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF VINEGAR.
CORED OUT CABBAGE WITH
THE EXTERIOR LEAVES TAKEN OFF.
YOU'RE JUST PLOPPING
THIS WHOLE THING IN THERE?
YEP.
IT'LL BOIL FOR ABOUT
15, 20 MINUTES.
TAKE THE LEAVES OFF.
WE LINE THE TRAY
WITH THE CABBAGE LEAVES
SO THE CABBAGE ROLLS DON'T BURN
WHEN THEY'RE COOKING.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN.
POUR IN THE RICE,
GROUND PORK.
HOLY MOLY.
SALT AND PEPPER,
LEMON PEPPER, TWO EGGS.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BINDER.
YOU GOT IT.
SPOTTING YOU
ON THE BOWL.
IT'S COMING TOGETHER.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA--
THE COOKED CABBAGE LEAVES,
HAVE THE LEAVES FACING
THIS DIRECTION.
WOW, BIG OLD SERVING
OF THAT.
OH, YEAH.
WRAP IT ONCE.
PUT THE SIDES IN.
SO THEY DON'T DRY OUT.
THAT'S A CABBAGE ROLL.
THESE GET LAID OUT.
PLACE SOME BUTTER ON TOP,
WE POUR SOME DICED TOMATOES.
THEN MORE CABBAGE LEAVES
GO ON TOP.
YOU GOT IT.
THIS WILL BAKE FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR AND A HALF AT 425.
REALLY?
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
TOMATO CREAM SAUCE.
START OFF WITH SOME BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME ONIONS.
PURéED.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME FLOUR.
A LITTLE BIT
OF A ROUX.
YEP. NEXT WE'VE GOT
TOMATO SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT, KEEP IT STIRRIN'.
CHICKEN STOCK, SALT.
AND LASTLY, THE CREAM.
YOU GOT IT.
WE'LL LET THIS
TIGHTEN UP...
YEP.
AND THIS IS WHAT GETS SERVED
ON TOP OF THE CABBAGE.
YEP, THEY'RE READY.
LET'S TAKE 'EM OUT.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
HERE THEY ARE.
CHECK THIS OUT.
BEFORE, THEY HAD PLASTIC WRAP
AND FOIL. TO KEEP THAT MOISTURE,
YOU JUST TAKE
THE CABBAGE LEAVES,
AND KEEP THE MOISTURE
LOCKED IN WITH THAT.
WE CALL IT A POLISH BURRITO.
POLISH BURRITO.
SOME SAUCE ON TOP.
NICE AND THICK.
THIS IS STICK-
TO-YOUR-RIB FOOD. MMM.
GOSH, THIS IS AWESOME.
THE CABBAGE IS SO TENDER.
BEYOND TENDER.
I LIKE THE GRIND OF THE PORK.
STILL GET SOME TEXTURE.
THE RICE IS STILL FIRM.
AND THEN YOU GET
THE SAUCE ON TOP OF IT.
MMM.
THAT MIGHT BE MY FAVORITE.
BUT IF YOU'RE MOWING THE LAWN,
JUST LET IT RUN TILL IT'S OUT
OF GAS AND GET DOWN HERE.
CABBAGE ROLL!
THE BEST CABBAGE ROLL
I'VE EVER HAD.
IT JUST HITS THE SPOT.
THIS IS PROBABLY THE REASON
THAT I STILL LIVE IN MINNESOTA.
BECAUSE OF
THE CABBAGE ROLL?
YEAH.
HERE'S ONE ORDER.
WE COME HERE
THREE, FOUR TIMES A WEEK.
REALLY?
ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
THIS IS THE BEST EASTERN
EUROPEAN FOOD THAT YOU CAN FIND.
EVERYTHING FROM POLISH
PEASANT PIE...
KIND OF LIKE
A SHEPHERD'S PIE
WITH POLISH SAUSAGE.
TO A CLASSIC HUNGARIAN
MEAT AND CABBAGE DISH.
FULL ORDER,
SZEGEDIN GOULASH.
MMM.
IT'S GOT
WHIZ, BANG, WOW IN THERE.
AND FOLKS AROUND HERE
TOP IT WITH ANOTHER
EASTERN EUROPEAN FAVORITE.
PIEROGIES,
AS I CALL THEM.
THE POLISH VERSION
OF POT STICKERS.
OR IF YOU'RE UKRAINIAN...
SIX VARENYKY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE FILLING
FOR THE MEAT VARENYKY.
ALL RIGHT, IT'S BOILED-DOWN
BEEF AND PORK.
STICKING IT THROUGH
THE BUFFALO CHOPPER.
YEP.
GARLIC CLOVES,
SOME PEPPER, SALT.
THAT IS SOME FINE SALT.
CHICKEN.
AND SOME SAUTéED ONIONS.
WE TURN IT ON,
STAND BACK.
GONNA LEAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF TEXTURE TO IT?
WE DO IT PRETTY FINE. THE FINER
IT IS, EASIER IT IS TO ROLL IT.
AS LONG AS YOU CAN GET THAT
TO START FORMING.
OKAY, WE GOOD?
WE'RE GOOD.
TAKE IT OUT.
ON WE GO TO MAKE
THE (mumbles).
VARENYKY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
COME ON, YOU CAN
SAY IT BY NOW.
VARENYKY?
THERE YOU GO.
I KEEP FORGE-NYKY.
THAT'S GOOD.
WE'RE MAKING THE DOUGH
FOR THE...
VARENYKY.
ALL RIGHT,
NOW YOU GOT IT.
SEE?
FIRST SOME EGGS,
FLOUR...
MMM.
BUTTERMILK...
WHOLE MILK?
YEP. WATER.
START IT ON ONE?
YEP. WE JUST LET IT GO.
WHENEVER IT LOOKS GOOD, WHENEVER
IT PULLS AWAY FROM THE BOWL.
THAT'S RIGHT. AND WE'RE GONNA
TAKE IT TO THE SHEETER.
ROLL IT OUT ALL NICE
AND PRETTY, PRETTY.
YEP. PUT IT
RIGHT ON DOWN.
NOW I'M GONNA SHOW YOU
MY FAVORITE THING.
DO YOU WANT ME TO HAVE
MY EYES CLOSED?
IF YOU WANT.
OKAY, YOU CAN OPEN
YOUR EYES.
OH, IT'S ONE OF THOSE
EXERCISE THINGS.
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
THAT'S AWESOME.
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
TAKE THE DOUGH AWAY--
THE LITTLE EXTRAS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FILL
THE VARENYKY.
RIGHT NOW-YKY.
BRING OVER OUR MEAT.
I'LL DO THE DOUGH HOLD,
YOU GIVE ME THE BALL.
IT'S A DEAL.
WOW, THERE'S A TON
GOES IN THAT.
OH, YEAH. SO WE JUST
WRAP IT AROUND, PINCH.
YOU DON'T WANT IT
TO OPEN
IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE BOILING PROCESS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
KEEP 'EM ON THE FLOUR TRAY
SO THEY ABSORB THE FLOUR
SO THEY DON'T GET ALL WET
FROM THE MOISTURE.
IF THERE'S TOO MUCH MOISTURE
IN THAT FILLING,
THEY'LL START
TO FALL APART.
YOU GOT IT. GET 'EM ALL MADE,
AND WE BOIL 'EM UP.
ALL RIGHT, SO, UH...
THEY'RE FLOATING.
YEP, VARENYKY ARE DONE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE 'EM OUT.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
WE'RE ROLLIN'.
THEY'RE HOT.
WHO'S EATING
ALL OF THIS?
YOU ARE.
BUT IT'S SWIMSUIT SEASON.
SOUR-CREAM-HORSERADISH MIX.
TOP IT OFF WITH SOME BUTTER--
THERE WE GO,
GET SOME BUTTER ON IT.
WHAT DO I HAVE HERE? SOME LOOK
DIFFERENT. WHAT ARE THOSE?
YOU GOT SOME
POTATO CHEESE HERE,
YOU GOT YOUR MEAT ONES HERE,
AND SAUERKRAUT.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
HAVE TO DIG IN.
DUMPLING MADNESS.
OH, YOU GOTTA DUNK IT
IN THE SOUR CREAM.
I'M SORRY.
THERE, THERE.
MMM. THAT'S SAUERKRAUT.
THE DOUGH IS OUTSTANDING.
LET'S GO WITH THE MEAT.
LET'S TRY.
MMM. TASTE A LITTLE OF THAT
GARLIC BITE IN THERE.
THE TEXTURE OF THE MEAT--
IT'S LIKE A POLISH RAVIOLI.
I LIKE IT.
POTATO CHEESE.
THOSE ARE MY FAVORITE.
MMM. YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK POTATO AND CHEESE
MIGHT BE MY FAVORITE, TOO.
YEP.
YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES IT?
THE HORSERADISH...
YEP.
IN THAT SOUR CREAM.
THOSE ARE GREAT.
VARENYKYS.
THIS IS STUFFED WITH
POTATOES AND CHEESE,
AND IT'S AWESOME.
ANYTHING ELSE?
CAN'T GO WRONG. YOU ORDER
ANYTHING YOU WANT.
HUNGARIAN SAUSAGE
WITH SAUERKRAUT.
YOU CAN GET YOUR EASTERN
EUROPEAN COOKED SAUSAGE.
IT'S ALL TRADITIONAL.
IT'S ALL NATURAL.
AND IT ALL COMES OUT
OF THIS MONSTER...
(as Darth Vader) LUKE,
I'LL MAKE YOUR SAUSAGE.
BY THE TON.
UP TO ABOUT 10,000
POUNDS A WEEK.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WHOA!
BORSCHT.
AT KRAMARCZUK'S
IN NORTHEAST MINNEAPOLIS...
SZEGEDIN GOULASH.
THREE GENERATIONS
OF THE KRAMARCZUK FAMILY
HAVE BEEN CRANKING OUT CLASSIC
EASTERN EUROPEAN RECIPES...
MMM.
SINCE 1954.
CABBAGE ROLL.
THIS IS FRESH, HANDMADE.
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING
IN THE CAFETERIA,
AND...
ON THE DELI SIDE,
THEY MAKE THEIR OWN SAUSAGE.
TONS OF DIFFERENT KINDS
OF SAUSAGES.
LITERALLY.
UP TO ABOUT
10,000 POUNDS A WEEK.
ALL TURNED OUT BY THIRD-
GENERATION FAMILY MEMBER
NICK KRAMARCZUK.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT TYPES
OF SAUSAGE DO YOU MAKE?
ANYWHERE FROM ABOUT 35 TO 60.
YOU GUYS KIND OF TAKE THIS
SAUSAGE THING SERIOUSLY, HUH?
VERY.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
HELLO...
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
KRAKOWSKA TODAY.
IT'S TRADITIONALLY
A POLISH LUNCHMEAT.
NICE WHITE FAT, SOME PORK LOIN
AND SOME PORK SIRLOIN.
START WITH OUR PORK FAT.
WATCH YOURSELF.
YOU GET SOME SHRAPNEL HERE.
GRIND IT REAL FINE.
IT'S LIKE HE'S
DELIVERING A BABY.
SET THAT ASIDE FOR NOW.
THROW IN OUR LOINS.
THAT IS NUTS.
TOSS IN THE SIRLOIN.
SO GETTING ONE OF THESE
FOR MY HOUSE.
LORI WOULD NOT BE HAPPY
ABOUT THIS.
YOU WANT TO GET IN THERE AND SEE
HOW BIG THE MIXER IS FIRST?
(as Darth Vader) LUKE,
I'LL MAKE YOUR SAUSAGE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU DONE?
(normal voice) YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
AM I DONE? THAT'S THE BEST
LINE OF ALL TIME.
WHAT WAS THAT
WE JUST PUT IN?
THE PORK FAT BASE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING--
WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
THAT'S IT.
WE'LL START WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
RIGHT IN THERE.
CURING AGENT,
WHITE PEPPER,
MAIZE.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
YOU GOT IT.
NOW WE MIX. MIGHT WANT TO KEEP
YOUR HEAD OUT OF IT THIS TIME.
LOOK AT THAT!
ADD SOME WATER TO MAKE
SURE IT'S NOT TOO DRY.
THAT'S ICE IN THERE, TOO,
TO KEEP IT COLD.
COLDER THE BETTER.
WE MAKING PâTé?
THAT'S WHAT'S GONNA
KEEP IT NICE AND FIRM
WHEN WE FINALLY SMOKE IT.
MAKES THAT MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE
IN MAKING THE SAUSAGE.
I WOULD HAVE NEVER
HAVE KNOWN THAT.
THE GROUND PORK LOIN.
GO.
SIRLOIN. MIX IT UP.
NOW WE PUT THE REST OF OUR SALT,
CURING AGENT...
OKAY.
THEN WE MIX AGAIN.
A LOT OF WORK FOR SAUSAGE.
READY?
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
DUDE, YOU GOTTA GET
RIGHT UP THERE, SON.
THERE YOU GO,
THERE YOU GO.
NOW WE LOAD UP
THE HOPPER.
YEP.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger) YAH,
TO LIFT AND PUT IT IN HERE.
(whistles, normal voice)
LOOK AT THIS.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO STUFF IT
INTO OUR CASING.
MAKE SURE THAT THE STUFFING'S
RIGHT UP AGAINST HERE,
OTHERWISE WE'RE GONNA GET
AIR IN THERE.
AIR IN THERE, OKAY.
I KNEW THAT I BROUGHT
GLASSES FOR A REASON.
WHOA!
NOW WE THREAD
THE CASING ON.
GRAB IT AS TIGHT
AS YOU CAN.
THAT'S AWESOME.
WE GET TO THE END THERE,
SLIDE IT OFF.
TIE 'EM OFF ON THE BOTTOM.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE SEAL. YOU DON'T WANT THIS
EXPLODING IN THE SMOKE HOUSE.
HANG 'EM UP THERE.
AND THEN INTO
THE SMOKER FOR...
12 TO 15 HOURS.
NO KIDDING?
YEP, PULL THESE OUT.
(whistles)
THAT'S AWESOME.
READY TO GO.
WHEEL THAT RIGHT UP
TO THE '67.
LET IT COOL, AND WE'LL BE READY
TO MAKE OUR SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
CUT THE END OFF HERE.
SLICE THAT UP.
FIRE AWAY.
NOT TOO THIN.
THAT'S OUR POLISH RYE.
SLICE THAT.
YOU GUYS MAKE
THE BREAD, ALSO?
YEP. STONE-GROUND
POLISH MUSTARD ON THERE.
YOU GUYS MAKE
THAT, ALSO.
YEP.
OF COURSE.
HORSERADISH MAYO,
HAVARTI CHEESE,
OUR KRAKOWSKA
THAT WE MADE...
OKAY.
SOME TOMATOES, CUCUMBER,
SOME LETTUCE.
THERE YOU HAVE IT--
KRAKOWSKA SANDWICH.
BIG SANDWICH.
MMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF SMOKINESS.
THIS HAS REALLY GOT SOME
TEXTURE, IT'S GOT DEPTH TO IT.
IT'S NOT OVERDONE
WITH SEASONING.
YOU SAW EVERYTHING
THAT WENT INTO IT.
YEAH.
NO MYSTERY MEAT.
THE BREAD'S OUTRAGEOUS.
ALL THE PRODUCE IS FRESH.
LITTLE BITE FROM THE MUSTARD.
DYNAMITE, MAN.
THANK YOU.
START TO FINISH,
GREAT JOB.
HERE'S YOUR
KRAKOWSKA SANDWICH.
THIS THING IS TERRIFIC.
LIKE A HAM SANDWICH,
BUT IT'S BETTER THAN THAT.
SZEGEDIN GOULASH.
A LITTLE FLAVOR
OF THE OLD COUNTRY.
CABBAGE ROLL
WITH KRAUT.
GOOD HAS, LIKE, STEPPING BACK
INTO MY GRANDMA'S KITCHEN.
FRENCH APPLE SAUSAGE.
THAT'S WHAT'S SO COOL
ABOUT THIS PLACE--
YOU GUYS MAKE IT ALL.
IMPRESSED.
I THINK YOUR GRANDFATHER
WOULD BE PRETTY HAPPY
TO SEE THIS
GOING ON.
I THINK SO, TOO.
NEXT STOP...
DINNER BELL FOR JANE
AND ROGER!
WE'RE HEADING
TO WEST VIRGINIA...
LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
WITH A COUPLE
OF TRIPLE "D" FANS...
EVERYTHING HERE
IS OVER THE TOP.
ON THEIR ULTIMATE
TRIPLE "D" ROAD TRIP.
UNBELIEVABLE.
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE COOL THINGS
ABOUT TRIPLE "D"
IS HEARING FROM ALL THE FANS
THAT ARE SO INSPIRED
BY THE SHOW.
YOU KNOW, THERE ARE ROAD TRIPS,
AND VISITING FIVE, TEN--
I MEAN, SOME ARE VISITING
DOZENS OF TRIPLE "D" LOCATIONS,
BUT THERE'S ONE COUPLE
THAT MAY BE THE KING
AND QUEEN OF IT ALL.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
ROGER AND JANE HOLME.
NOW--LOOK AT THE GEAR,
LOOK AT THE BIKE,
AND YOU ARE ON TOUR--
AS MUCH AS I'M ON TOUR
SHOOTING TRIPLE "D,"
SO ARE YOU--HOW MANY PLACES
HAVE YOU BEEN TO?
OUR 100th WAS HILLBILLY HOT DOGS
IN WEST VIRGINIA.
YOU JUST HIT 100.
WE DID.
100.
LISTEN, IF YOU GUYS
DON'T SLOW DOWN,
YOU'RE GONNA START
MAKING ME LOOK BAD, OKAY?
I'M GOING ONTO 400,
AND YOU'VE ALREADY DONE 100.
HOW WAS THE VISIT?
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
GREAT PEOPLE, GREAT FOOD.
CAN'T GO WRONG.
AWESOME. LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT WHAT YOU GUYS DID.
YEE-HAW! WE MADE IT.
HERE WE ARE.
100! LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY
UNBELIEVABLE.
MUST BE THE HOLMES.
HEY!
OWNERS SHARIE AND SONNY KNIGHT
GAVE 'EM THE SAME WARM WELCOME
THEY GAVE ME...
OH!
WHEN I STOPPED BY TO CHECK OUT
THEIR HOMEWRECKER HOT DOG...
HOMEWRECKER!
ISN'T THAT WONDERFUL?
YEAH!
AND THEIR SINGLE WIDE BURGER.
IS THERE ANY
ON MY FACE?
(bell dings)
DINNER BELL
FOR JANE AND ROGER!
NOW IT WAS JANE AND ROGER'S
TURN TO CHOW DOWN.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE
KICK TO IT.
THAT IS WORTH
THE DRIVE RIGHT THERE.
THIS PLACE IS MORE
THAN WE EVER EXPECTED IT TO BE.
JANE AND ROGER CAME ALL THE WAY
FROM MINNESOTA.
THIS IS THEIR TRIPLE "D"
100th STOP.
AND WHEREVER THEY GO,
THEY'RE RUNNING INTO FOLKS
DOING THE SAME THING THEY ARE.
YOU GUYS REALLY
COME FROM FLORIDA?
WE DID, YEAH.
WE CAME HERE FROM COLUMBUS,
OHIO, JUST FOR LUNCH TODAY.
I WILL GO AN HOUR OUT OF THE WAY
TO COME FIND SOME FUNKY PLACE.
THIS IS WHAT
TRIPLE "D" IS ABOUT.
LIKE I ALWAYS SAY, SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
JANE AND ROGER HAVE BEEN
DOING IT FOR TWO YEARS.
45 RESTAURANTS
AND 13 STATES.
THIS IS JUST IN THAT
ONE YEAR, HUH?
IT IS.
OH, THIS IS AMAZING.
HANK'S CREEKSIDE
IN CALIFORNIA.
FABULOUS PLACE TO GO.
PANINI PETE'S
IN FAIR HOPE, ALABAMA.
THAT IS OUR 60th
TRIPLE "D" PLACE.
WE'RE HAVING A BALL.
WE'VE MADE LIFELONG FRIENDS.
SO WHAT'S
YOUR FAVORITE MEAL?
WEST VIRGINIA DOG!
RIGHT HERE IS OUR FAVORITE.
RIGHT NOW IS OUR FAVORITE.
FOR THEM TO HAVE ACCOMPLISHED
100 IS JUST OVER THE TOP.
WE THOUGHT, WE GOTTA DO
SOMETHING CRAZY.
BRING IT ON IN.
WE WANTED TO SPELL OUT
100, FOOD STYLE.
TWO SINGLE WIDES,
A HOMEWRECKER!
100.
UNBELIEVABLE.
THIS IS REALLY FUN.
HERE WE GO.
YEAH!
PUSH IT, PUSH IT.
YOUR TURN.
I'M ALL OVER THIS.
IT'S OVERWHELMING,
YOU KNOW?
OH, MY WORD.
IT IS REALLY GOOD.
THIS IS AS MUCH POUNDAGE
AS WE'VE HAD IN 100,
JUST RIGHT HERE. WELL,
THIS HAS TO GO IN THE BOOK.
WOW. 100 LOCATIONS.
IT'S BEEN A GOOD TIME?
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
WE'RE GONNA CATCH YOU.
GOOD LUCK, YOU GUYS.
THANKS.
SO WATCH OUT,
I'M GONNA BE LOOKING FOR YOU
ON THE NEXT
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HERE YOU GO.
HEY...
(laughter)