HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THE MAMA'S SPECIAL.
TRIED...
WOW, LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
AND TRUE.
HASN'T CHANGED
SINCE I WAS A KID.
IN WASHINGTON, D.C...
CHEERS.
A 63-YEAR-OLD DIVE BAR...
RIGHT ON CAPITAL HILL.
DOING GRANDDAD'S COOKIN'...
HERE'S YOUR JOE'S
WEST VIRGINIA SANDWICH.
WITH A TWIST.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS BON TON SAUCE?
IN KITTERY, MAINE...
SEAFOOD BASKET SPECIAL.
THE LOCAL LANDMARK...
CLAMS ARE SO GOOD HERE.
WHERE THEY'VE BEEN
CRANKING OUT THE CLAMS...
DROPPING CLAMS.
AND LOADING UP THE LOBSTER...
(man) LOBSTER STEW.
SINCE 1956.
MMM. THIS IS A TON
OF LOBSTER.
AND IN ANAHEIM, CALIFORNIA...
OLD-SCHOOL ITALIAN.
THE THIRD GENERATION JOINT...
THEY REALLY DO
GOOD STUFF HERE.
SCRATCH-MAKING
FAMILY FAVORITES...
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE DOMERY SAUCE?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FOR 45 YEARS.
WOW. OH, NICE JOB.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
NOW THE NAME OF THE SHOW IS
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHEN WE FIRST STARTED,
PEOPLE WOULD SAY,
"WELL, WE'RE NOT A DINER
AND WE'RE NOT A DRIVE-IN,
SO DOES THAT
MAKE US A DIVE?"
I'D SAY, NO, NO, NO, NO, IT'S
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
AND EVERYTHING IN BETWEEN,
BUT EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE,
WE FIND A PLACE THAT SAYS,
"NO, WITHOUT QUESTION,
WE ARE A DIVE!"
SO HERE I AM, THREE BLOCKS
FROM THE NATION'S CAPITAL,
AT A PLACE WHERE THEY'RE SERVING
EVERYONE FROM SENATORS
TO BLUE COLLAR,
AND THEY SAY WITHOUT QUESTION,
THEY'RE A DIVE.
THIS IS TUNE INN.
BARBECUE SANDWICH,
COMING UP.
THIS IS THE PLACE TO BE.
HI, GUYS. HOW'S IT GOIN'?
THERE'S ANIMALS STICKING OUT
OF THE WALL.
IT'S THE QUINTESSENTIAL
CAPITAL HILL ESTABLISHMENT.
FRIED CHICKEN,
BAKED BEANS.
YOU ARE THE WHAT?
A DIVE,
AND VERY PROUD OF IT.
SINCE '47, WHEN JOE NARDELLI
GOT THINGS ROLLING.
HE'S THE ONE THAT MADE IT
INTO THE BAR AND RESTAURANT?
YES.
MOZZARELLA STICKS.
63 YEARS LATER,
GRANDDAUGHTER LISA...
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
IS RUNNING THE JOINT.
ALL RIGHT, ENJOY.
AND WITH FORMER MARINE
MIKE TATE IN THE KITCHEN...
FISH AND CHIPS--
APPROXIMATELY ONE HALF MINUTE.
THEY'RE KEEPING GRANDPA JOE'S
TRADITIONS ALIVE...
PICK UP, PICK UP!
LIKE THIS ONE...
JOE'S WEST VIRGINIA.
TOPPED WITH A SERGEANT MIKE
ORIGINAL.
BON TON SAUCE.
YES, SIR.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
IS BON TON SAUCE?
A MULTI-PURPOSE SAUCE
THAT CAN BE EATEN
WITH JUST ABOUT ANY
AND EVERYTHING.
THANK YOU, SERGEANT.
PROCEED.
MAYONNAISE, KETCHUP,
BLACK PEPPER.
PAPRIKA--
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
HORSERADISH.
(neighs)
THAT'S RIGHT. WHISK ALL
THE INGREDIENTS TOGETHER.
MIX IT TO TASTE.
READY FOR YOUR TASTE.
HERE WE GO. OH, I LIKE THAT.
THAT'S A LITTLE THOUSAND ISLAND
GONE WILD RIGHT THERE.
I'LL TELL YOU.
SERGEANT, WHAT ARE WE
ONTO NOW, SIR?
THE ROAST BEEF
FOR JOE'S WEST VIRGINIA.
PROCEED.
WE'LL BE ADDING CELERY.
WE'LL BE ADDING CARROTS.
CUT UNIFORMLY
IN MILITARY STYLE.
ABOUT A PITCHER OF WATER,
BOTH SIDES.
IF WE POUR INTO THAT END
OF THE PAN,
WON'T IT GET TO THAT END?
EVENTUALLY,
BUT IN THE MARINES,
WE DON'T WAIT.
WE DO THINGS PRECISELY.
THERE WE GO.
SEASON IT ALL WITH SALT.
WE'RE ALL READY FOR THE OVEN.
WE'LL BE COVERING
THE MEAT WITH FOIL.
INTO THE BIG OVEN.
AT A TEMPERATURE OF 400--
2 1/2 TO 3 HOURS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
DO WHAT WITH IT?
AFTER IT COOLS,
CUT IT IN FOUR.
TAKE OFF ALL THE EXCESS FAT,
DOWN TO THE LEAN MEAT.
AFTER IT'S TRIMMED,
WE'LL BE SLICING IT.
(whistles)
HOW ARE WE GONNA
HEAT THIS UP, SARGE?
WE'LL BE ADDING JUST A LITTLE
BUTTER TO THE GRILL.
THROW IT DOWN.
NEXT WE'LL BE ADDING
RYE BREAD WITH AMERICAN CHEESE,
BON TON SAUCE.
SO THAT GETS ADDED ON
WHILE IT'S ON THE GRILL.
EXACTLY. NOW THAT THE MEAT
IS NICE AND WARM,
PILE IT VERY HIGH.
BON TON SAUCE ON THE MEAT.
THE RYE BREAD.
TAKE A PEEK AT THE BREAD.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
THAT IS VERY NICE.
REMOVE IT FROM THE GRILL,
IT'S CUT,
NOW IT'S ALL READY
FOR TASTE.
YOU GUYS READY FOR THIS?
MMM. THAT IS A GOOD SANDWICH.
NICE MEDIUM-RARE MEAT.
SUPER TENDER. I'D ORDER THIS
SANDWICH EVERY TIME I CAME IN.
I LIKE THE BON TON.
WAY TO GO, BUDDY.
THANK YOU.
FEEL LIKE I SHOULD SALUTE.
HERE'S YOUR
JOE'S WEST VIRGINIA SANDWICH.
REALLY TENDER, AND WHATEVER
THEY DO WITH THE SAUCE IS CRAZY.
REALLY ADDS FLAVOR TO THE
ROAST BEEF. IT'S OUTSTANDING.
BURGERS--
APPROXIMATELY TWO MINUTES.
IT'S GOOD BAR FOOD.
PATTY MELT UP.
RIGHT ON CAPITAL HILL.
EVERYONE COMES IN,
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT
YOUR BACKGROUND MIGHT BE.
FROM THE LOCAL
FIREHOUSE...
A LOT OF FIREMEN,
A LOT OF COPS.
TO CAPITAL HILL.
SENATOR GEORGE LeMIEUX
FROM FLORIDA,
HOW DO YOU END UP
AT TUNE INN?
UH, THIS IS A PLACE I CAME TO
WHEN I WAS IN LAW SCHOOL.
REAL PEOPLE COME TO GET A BEER,
HAVE A CHEESEBURGER
AND HANG OUT WITH EACH OTHER.
CHEERS.
IT'S A REAL PLACE.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GREAT.
CHILI CHEDDAR BURGER.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE HOME WHEN
YOU HAVE A BURGER HERE.
FROM THE BASIC...
THE SWISS BURGER--
SO GOOD.
TO BEER-BATTERED.
IT'S CRUNCHY, IT'S BAD FOR YOU,
AND IT'S AMAZING.
SERGEANT, WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
BEER-BATTERED BURGER.
FANTASTIC.
START WITH FRESH GROUND BEEF
MADE INTO A PATTY.
SEE HOW HE STOPS EVERYTHING
AND ENDS IT UP?
THAT'S THE WAY THE MARINES
DO IT. READY FOR THE GRILL.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
NEXT WE'LL BE MAKING
THE BEER BATTER.
FLOUR, PAPRIKA,
SEASON-ALL SALT...
AND PUSH-UPS.
50, TO BE EXACT.
WE'RE GONNA BE ADDING BEER.
YOU WANT ME TO GET YOU
SOME MORE BEER IN THERE?
YES, SIR.
OKAY, GOOD,
JUST TELL ME WHEN.
OKAY, YOU CAN POUR
IT IN NOW.
(quietly) THAT'LL BE GOOD.
WHISPERING NOW.
ARE WE GOING COVERT?
(normal voice) ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S IT.
SO WHAT HAPPENS NOW,
WE COOK THE BURGER...
FLIP IT, BROWN BOTH SIDES.
LET IT COOL
A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT,
INTO THE BEER BATTER.
COAT IT, AND FROM THE BEER
BATTER IT GOES INTO THE FRYER.
OKAY, HERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT. DRAIN OFF
THE EXCESS.
GOES BACK ON THE GRILL.
MELT CHEESE, AND JUST SLIDE
IT RIGHT ON.
GOTCHA.
VERY SIMPLE PROCEDURE.
ALL READY FOR YOUR PLATE.
THIS IS HOW SHE
ROCKS AND ROLLS.
YES, SIR. ADD ONIONS,
WHATEVER YOU LIKE.
I'M JUST STALLING
RIGHT NOW,
BECAUSE THIS IS GONNA
BE LIKE 9,000 DEGREES.
HERE WE GO.
WOW, THAT WORKS.
NICE LITTLE BITE TO IT.
THERE'S A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
THAT GOES ONTO THE BATTER,
AND DRILL SERGEANT CHEF
OVER HERE PRECISELY COOKED IT
SO WHEN IT WENT INTO THE FRYER,
IT CAME OUT ABOUT A MEDIUM.
THAT'S A GOOD
DEEP-FRIED BURGER.
TWO BEER-BATTERED
BURGERS WORKING.
IT'S PRETTY SPECIAL.
(man) WE'RE TALKING EVERYTHING
A MAN WANTS IN A BURGER.
THEY SERVE YOU
WHAT YOU WANT RIGHT NOW.
(man) WHEN YOU ORDER.
COMIN' UP!
SARGE, WITH ALL OF THESE
FIREMEN THAT ARE OUT THERE,
I THINK I NEED
TO MAKE A TRIBUTE BURGER
FOR THE D.C.F.D.
SOUNDS GREAT.
I GOT A DE-BLING FOR THIS.
LET'S GO WITH TWO PATTIES,
LET'S MAKE 'EM NICE AND FLAT.
THROW DOWN.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WHILE THOSE ARE GOING,
PICKLES AND JALAPEÑO SLICES
INTO THE BEER BATTER--
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
OKAY, I GOT SOME BACON, HOOK 'EM
UP WITH A COUPLE GRILLED CHEESE.
WHAT ELSE YOU THINK
WE NEED TO PUT ON THIS?
LET'S TRY
SOME ROAST BEEF.
GET SOME ONIONS, MUSHROOMS,
GOTTA HAVE BELL PEPPER.
LOOKIN' GOOD, BUDDY.
BARBECUE SAUCE.
AN ANIMAL. (growls)
JALAPEÑOS AND PICKLES
ARE DONE.
THAT'S A GRILLED CHEESE.
HOOK THESE BURGERS UP--PEPPERS,
THE ONIONS, AND THE MUSHROOM.
SWISS CHEESE.
FANTASTIC.
READY TO SEE THIS?
ONE GRILLED CHEESE,
BURGER PATTY, AND THE BACON.
GET A COUPLE FOUNDATIONAL
BUILDING BINDERS.
I THINK WE'RE JUST MISSING
SOMETHING, BUDDY.
WE HAVE TO HAVE FRIES.
TOSS 'EM IN A LITTLE HOT SAUCE,
GET 'EM ON THE PLATE.
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
WE'RE ALMOST THERE, BUDDY.
HERE WE GO--PIECE OF TOAST,
ROAST BEEF WITH BARBECUE SAUCE,
FRIED PICKLES,
FRIED JALAPEÑOS,
BON TON SAUCE,
ONE MORE PIECE OF TOAST,
PATTY WITH CHEESE,
THE LAST GRILLED CHEESE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT, MY FRIEND,
IS A SANDWICH.
FIRE THAT MISSILE,
SOLDIER.
YOU GOT IT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IN HONOR OF THE BRAVE FIREMEN
HERE IN D.C.,
THE TRIPLE "D"
D.C.F.D.
I'M IN.
I WILL REMOVE
THE SABER.
THERE YOU GO. GET AFTER THAT!
OWN THAT. GET AFTER THAT!
CAN'T GET HIS MOUTH
AROUND IT.
MMM.
GOOD STUFF?
I'M IN HEAVEN.
YOU'RE IN NEXT ON THIS.
OH!
FRIED CHICKEN.
THANK YOU.
THE FOOD IS GREAT
AND THE PEOPLE ARE GREAT.
IS THAT THE FOURTH GENERATION?
FOURTH GENERATION.
I'M RAISING THE BAR STAFF.
SO THIS IS THE NEXT GENERATION
OF THE TUNE INN?
YES.
I THINK YOUR DAD AND YOUR
GRANDDAD WOULD BE PROUD OF YOU.
THANK YOU.
I'LL TELL YOU,
WHAT A DIVE.
UP NEXT...
CLAM DINNER.
WE'RE HEADED TO MAINE...
CLAMS ARE ABSOLUTELY
FANTASTIC.
TO CLAM IT UP.
MMM, THAT'S A LOT
OF FRESH CLAM TASTE.
I THINK I'M HAVING A LITTLE
TRIPLE "D" DéJà VU.
REMEMBER WHEN
WE WERE AT J.T. FARNHAM'S,
YOU KNOW,
IN SOUTH ESSEX, MASSACHUSETTS,
RIGHT BY THE WATERWAY,
AND THEY WERE FRYING UP THOSE
LITTLE WHOLE-BELLY CLAMS?
THIS PLACE COULD BE ITS TWIN.
IT'S RIGHT BY A WATERWAY,
EXCEPT THIS TIME IT'S ON ROUTE 1
IN KITTERY, MAINE.
THIS IS BOB'S CLAM HUT.
CLAM DINNER.
CLAMS ARE ABSOLUTELY
FANTASTIC.
THE CLAMS ARE SO GOOD HERE.
DROPPING CLAMS.
THE CRUNCH WHEN IT GOES
INTO YOUR MOUTH--SO GOOD.
HERE YOU GO,
TWO CLAM BASKETS.
IT HASN'T CHANGED
SINCE I WAS A KID--
THE FLAVOR--
EVERYTHING ABOUT IT.
THANKS
TO MICHAEL LANDGARTEN.
QUART OF CLAMS.
I USED TO EAT HERE,
BEFORE I BOUGHT IT.
FROM ORIGINAL OWNER BOB KRAFT,
WHO OPENED THIS PLACE
BACK IN THE '50s.
IT WAS ALWAYS ABOUT
HOW I WAS GONNA FIGURE OUT
HOW TO DO JUST WHAT BOB
WAS DOING...
FISH DINNER.
NOT CHANGE WHAT BOB WAS DOING.
I HAD TOTAL RESPECT.
AND MORE THAN
TWO DECADES LATER...
CLAM DINNERS.
HE'S STILL DOING IT
BOB'S WAY.
I'M HAVING BOB'S FRIED CLAMS.
THEY'RE JUST DELICIOUS.
AND LILLIAN'S WAY.
WOULD YOU RATHER HAVE
THE LILLIAN CLAMS?
LILLIAN CLAM--IS THAT
A NEW--NEW KIND OF CLAM?
WE HAVE A LONG-TERM EMPLOYEE,
OUR BEST, LILLIAN.
SHE WOULD ALWAYS ARGUE WITH ME,
"YOU GOTTA PUT THE CLAMS
IN THE WASH FIRST--
THEY'RE BETTER LIKE THAT."
SO THE IDEA IS
THERE'S THE BOB'S ORIGINAL
THAT GO INTO
JUST A DRY FLOUR...
YOU BET.
AND THEN THERE'S
THE LILLIAN CLAM.
LILLIAN GOES IN EGG WASH
BEFORE IT GOES IN FLOUR.
GIVE ME THE FLOUR
BREAKDOWN.
THIS IS CORN FLOUR.
CORN FLOUR FROM CORN,
AND YOU GOT...
THIS IS WHITE FLOUR.
FLOUR FROM WHEAT.
RIGHT.
IS IT 50/50?
IT'S NOT.
SO THREE CORN
AND THREE FLOUR...
AND TWO WHITE.
AND SI--AND ONE--
AND THEN FOUR--
SO THAT'S FOUR CORN?
YOU'RE TRYING
TO MESS ME UP.
THAT'S FOUR CORN...
IT WAS THREE CORN
AND TWO WHITE.
WHATEVER YOU WANT
TO CALL IT.
NOW I'M GONNA MIX IT.
IN CONSIDERATION
TO HOW MUCH YOU DO IN A DAY,
HOW MANY OF THE BOWLS LIKE THIS
COULD YOU GO THROUGH?
40.
YOU'LL MAKE 40 BOWLS?
YOU'RE JAMMIN'
WHEN YOU'RE CLAMMIN'.
WE'RE CRAZY.
ALL RIGHT,
SO NOW THE FLOUR IN?
YES.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE FIRST?
MAKE THE BOB'S TRADITIONAL
FRIED CLAM.
OKAY. YOU ALWAYS JUST DROP 'EM
RIGHT IN THE FLOUR LIKE THAT?
YEAH, THEY GO RIGHT IN,
AND AS BOB'S WIFE TAUGHT ME,
YOU GOTTA GET YOUR FINGERS IN
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THE NECKS.
OKAY.
SHAKE OFF THE EXCESS.
THAT'S IT?
NOW THEY GO
INTO THE FRYER.
NOW IT'S TIME FOR?
EGG WASH.
WHAT ARE WE DOING
WITH THE EGG WASH?
WELL, THIS IS SPECIFIC
TO THE LILLIAN CLAMS.
FIRST, SIX EGGS,
AND THEN WE'LL MIX IT UP.
STAND BACK.
OKAY.
AND THEN EVAPORATED MILK.
MAKE IT A LITTLE BIT SWEET.
YES. THIS IS THE HARDEST PART
OF THE WHOLE THING.
YOU'RE GONNA SPILL IT.
OH, OH!
BEEN AT THIS
A LITTLE WHILE.
NICE.
NOW FILL IT UP WITH MILK.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S A LOT OF WASH.
READY TO MAKE CLAMS?
I'VE BEEN DYING TO.
OKAY. JUST ONE EXTRA STEP--
CLAMS GO INTO THE EGG WASH.
SO JUST A LITTLE BIT
MORE MOISTURE.
YEP.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLAVOR.
NEXT TO THE SIFTER.
NOW THEY GO
INTO THE FRYER.
SO IN COMES
THE TOMATO FLAT BOX.
AND THIS IS HOW THEY'RE
NORMALLY DRIED OFF?
YEP.
(whistles) OKAY.
AND OUR NEW FRIEND
IS LILLIAN.
SO WE'VE GOT
THE BOB'S ORIGINALS.
MMM. THAT'S A LOT
OF FRESH CLAM TASTE.
AND THESE ARE
THE LILLIAN'S.
IT AIN'T GONNA BE EASY.
NOW WITH TARTAR SAUCE.
BOB'S CLAMS ARE KIND OF
THE PURITAN STYLE.
A LITTLE DREDGE
FOR A LITTLE CRUNCH.
MMM. KEEPS IN
SOME OF THE MOISTURE.
AND THE LILLIAN METHOD,
I THINK,
IS WHAT THE MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS WANT IN FRIED SEAFOOD.
THEY WANT A LITTLE CRUNCH,
THEY WANT SOME TEXTURE--
BUT THEN AGAIN...
(laughs)
MMM. WHEN YOU'RE USING CLAMS
THAT ARE THIS FRESH,
YOU REALLY DON'T NEED
TO DO ANYTHING TO THEM.
WHERE'S THE DRUMROLL?
I LOVE THE CRUNCH-IFICATION,
BUT I GOTTA GO
BOB'S ORIGINALS.
AND IT'S KILLING ME,
'CAUSE I LIKE LILLIAN
A LOT BETTER THAN YOU.
NOW I'VE GIVEN
MY TWO CENTS.
I THINK THERE'S A BETTER PERSON
TO STEP IN
TO GIVE THAT ALL-AMERICAN
FRIED CLAM PERSPECTIVE,
MY RIGHT-HAND MAN,
MY SON HUNTER FIERI.
OKAY.
IS THIS BOB'S?
YEP. I WANT YOU
TO GIVE ME A RUNDOWN.
NICE FULL CHOW.
YOU CAN TELL THIS KID CAN EAT.
IT'S GOOD.
THIS IS THE LILLIAN.
LILLIAN.
I WANT TO HEAR YOUR PERSPECTIVE,
WHAT YOU LIKE ABOUT THIS ONE
AND WHAT YOU LIKE
ABOUT THAT ONE.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT BOB'S
IS IT'S CHEWY
AND IT'S MORE CLAM FLAVOR,
AND LILLIAN'S IS MORE
OF A, YOU KNOW, FRIED.
LILLIAN.
WOW.
LILLIAN!
"GOOD BOY," SHE SAYS.
SPLIT RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE
IN THE FIERI FAMILY.
GOT TWO CLAM DINNERS,
ONE LILLIAN.
WE ORDERED BOTH CLAMS.
ONE BOB STYLE.
I LIKE THE LILLIAN'S CLAMS,
AND MY WIFE LIKES
THE BOB'S CLAMS.
MMM.
AROUND HERE, EVERYONE HAS
THEIR OWN FAVORITE.
YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
IT HAS TO BE
THE FISH AND CHIPS.
THE LOBSTER ROLL--
THE ROLLS ARE JUST PACKED.
OH, DON'T EVEN PUT
THAT NEXT TO ME.
YOU WON'T EVEN
GET A PIECE BACK.
JUST FULL OF LOBSTER.
AND SO IS THIS.
LOBSTER STEW.
OKAY, IT'S ALL UP TO YOU,
AND THE LOBSTER STEW.
YOU READY?
OKAY, WE TURN
THIS BEAST ON.
THAT WAS BUTTER
THAT JUST WENT DOWN.
THAT WAS BUTTER.
ONIONS.
OKAY, SO WE CARAMELIZE
THE ONIONS.
LOBSTER STOCK.
POTATOES.
YES. CHIVES, PARSLEY,
CAYENNE PEPPER, BLACK PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT.
NOW WAS THIS
BOB'S RECIPE?
NO, THIS ONE'S MINE.
CARROT, CELERY.
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
OKAY.
SIMMER IT, LET THE POTATOES
COOK DOWN, ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
ONCE THE POTATOES ARE RIGHT,
WE'RE ADDING MILK, CREAM.
THERE YOU GO.
BRING THAT TO A BOIL,
AND THAT'S OUR BASE.
THEN IT'S TIME
TO SAUTé THE LOBSTER,
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO?
WE ARE GOOD TO GO.
LET'S DO IT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL.
OKAY.
AND WE WANT TO CHOP UP
THE LOBSTER MEAT
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THAT'S A LOT
OF LOBSTER MEAT.
TOO MUCH?
THERE'S NEVER TOO MUCH.
I KNOW, THAT'S WHAT
I'M SAYIN'.
OKAY.
LOBSTER MEAT GOES IN.
COOKING THE LOBSTER
A LITTLE BIT.
OH, YEAH.
A LITTLE BIT OF SHERRY.
AND THAT'S
INTO THE POT?
YEP, THIS GOES RIGHT INTO
THE BASE THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
SEE, I LIKE
THE SHERRY TOUCH.
THERE WE GO.
WE'RE READY.
IT'S REALLY THAT MUCH LOBSTER
TO THAT MUCH STEW?
IT REALLY IS.
(whistles)
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
CHUNK OF LOBSTER
I JUST GOT WAS SO BIG.
IT REALLY NEEDED
A FORK AND A KNIFE.
THERE'S MORE LOBSTER THAN
THERE IS ANYTHING IN HERE.
MMM. MY FAVORITE BESIDES
THE GREAT LOBSTER FLAVOR
IS THE FACT THAT YOU HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE SHERRY.
GIVES THAT NICE,
ROUNDED FINISH TO IT. MMM.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
THIS IS A TON OF LOBSTER.
GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU.
LOBSTER STEW.
I LOVE IT. IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITE THINGS.
CLAM DINNER
AND LOBSTER ROLL.
IT'S ALL SO GOOD.
EVERYTHING YOU'VE HAD?
I EAT EVERYTHING.
JUST SHOVE--
JUST PUT IT AWAY.
I COULD EAT ALL THIS.
SEAFOOD BASKET SPECIAL.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH,
IT'S ALWAYS FAST,
AND IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
QUALITY PRODUCT
AND BY QUALITY PEOPLE.
HALF PINT OF OYSTERS.
THIS IS AN EXPERIENCE.
THANKS FOR HAVING US, MAN.
OH, IT WAS A PLEASURE.
NEXT STOP...
VEAL PARMESAN.
THANK YOU.
WE'RE HEADING TO CALIFORNIA...
HOMEMADE.
FOR OLD-SCHOOL ITALIAN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO I'M CRUISING DOWN
BALL ROAD,
ABOUT 2 MILES
WEST OF DISNEYLAND,
AND I CALLED MY BUDDY
GARY MAGGETTI, I SAID,
"HEY, 'GAIR,' YOU WANT
TO MEET ME AT THIS 45-YEAR-OLD
ITALIAN JOINT WHERE THEY'RE
ROCKING IT OUT OLD SCHOOL?"
AND HE GOES, "WHAT, YOU, UH,
YOU GOING TO COZZA'S?"
I SAID, "HOW DID YOU KNOW
I'M GOING TO COZZA'S?"
HE SAYS, "COZZA'S--
EVERYBODY KNOWS COZZA'S."
THIS IS MAMA COZZA'S.
SPAGHETTI WITH MEATBALLS.
OLD-SCHOOL ITALIAN.
MEDIUM MAMA'S SPECIAL.
LOVE THE PIZZA.
VEAL PARMESAN.
THIS IS MY BUDDY GARY,
AND THIS IS HIS FAMILY
THE MAGGETTIS.
WHAT MAKES COZZA'S
SO POPULAR?
YOU KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE GONNA GET.
THE FOOD'S GONNA BE DELICIOUS.
EVERYONE'S GONNA BE FRIENDLY.
HI, JACK,
HOW ARE YOU?
BEEN THAT WAY
SINCE '65,
WHEN FRANK COZZA
BOUGHT THE PLACE.
SHERRY GOING IN.
AND THESE DAYS, FRANK JR.
IS AT THE STOVE.
HAS IT CHANGED?
NO, SAME GREAT TASTE.
HOMEMADE.
INCLUDING
20 SCRATCH-MADE SAUCES.
ALFREDO SAUCE GOING ON.
WHATEVER COMBINATION YOU WANT,
THEY'LL DO FOR YOU.
NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
IT'LL BE ON THE MENU.
LIKE THIS ONE.
DOMERY SAUCE--IT'S GOT
CLAMS, IT'S GOT SAUSAGE.
DICK DOMERY WAS A GOOD
FRIEND OF MY FATHER'S.
HE CAME IN ONE DAY, SAID,
"I'M TIRED OF RED CLAM SAUCE."
PUT SOME SAUSAGE IN IT,
PUT EXTRA GARLIC,
AND I SAID, "OKAY,
NO PROBLEM."
LET'S GET INTO IT, MAN.
ALL RIGHT. FIRST WE'RE
GONNA MAKE SAUSAGE.
SO YOU GOT A BONELESS
PORK SHOULDER.
BUTTERFLYING OUT A BUTT.
SEE THAT TECHNIQUE RIGHT THERE?
YOU GONNA
CUBE IT UP?
NO, JUST STRIPS
SO IT'LL FIT
INTO THE GRINDER.
I LOVE THAT NOISE.
I TRIED TO GET IT
AS A RINGTONE.
ADD THE GARLIC.
SAVE A COUPLE OF PIECES
FOR AFTER I PUT THE GARLIC IN.
SO SOMETHING
CHASES IT OUT.
RIGHT. PUT IT
ONTO THE MIXER.
AND THEN WE'LL SEASON IT.
YOU GOT IT. FENNEL.
LOT OF FENNEL.
KOSHER SALT, CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
AND BLACK PEPPER.
THAT'S IT. LET IT HAVE
A LITTLE MIX-MIX.
AND WE'RE DONE. NOW WE JUST
PAN THE SAUSAGE.
OKAY.
FORM IT UP.
YOU CAN SMELL THAT FENNEL.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
350 FOR AN HOUR AND 40
TO 2 HOURS.
THEN WE BRING IT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT
COOL DOWN.
SCORE IT ACROSS,
BRING IT ACROSS AGAIN,
AND THEN WE'VE GOT
OUR SAUSAGE.
LOOK AT THAT.
DON'T SAY "RESEMBLANCE."
MMM, THAT IS AWESOME.
NOW TO THE BUFFALO CHOPPER.
FOR A CONSISTENT GRIND.
GET THIS ALL DONE, AND WE
GO MAKE THE DOMERY SAUCE.
THE DOMERY SAUCE.
OKAY, WELL,
FIRE IT UP.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR MAMA'S SAUCE.
OLIVE OIL.
THIS IS THE HOUSE SAUCE,
WHICH GETS USED
IN A VARIETY OF OTHER SAUCES,
KIND OF LIKE THE MOTHER SAUCE.
CORRECT.
MAMA SAUCE.
ADD OUR CHOPPED ONIONS,
PARSLEY, BELL PEPPER
AND CHOPPED GARLIC. STIR IT UP,
GET OUR SMALL PADDLE.
YES, 'CAUSE EVERYTHING
AT COZZA'S--PETITE IN GENERAL.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
SWEET BASIL, AND OREGANO.
GOT IT.
LET THAT COOK UP. NOW WE ADD
OUR GROUND TOMATOES.
(whistles)
YOU TOOK THE TOMATOES
OUT OF THE CAN, GROUND 'EM UP,
AND PUT 'EM IN
THE 5-GALLON BUCKETS?
YES.
WHOA. THIS GUY'S GETTING
SERIOUS ABOUT THIS.
NOW IT'S TAKING
A LOT OF TIME.
TAKES A LOT OF TIME
TO DO THAT?
NO, WE DO ABOUT--
WAY TO BACK UP MY STATEMENT.
MORE GROUND TOMATO.
OKAY.
NOW WE'LL STIR IT UP.
TOMATO PASTE--
ONE MORE CAN.
YOU LET THE PASTE
GET DOWN IN THERE.
STIR IT UP.
HOW LONG IS THAT
GONNA SIMMER?
HOUR TO AN HOUR AND A HALF.
THEN WE ADD CORNSTARCH
AS A THICKENER,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
AND THEN WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN?
WE'RE MAKING
THE DOMERY SAUCE.
PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF MAMA'S SAUCE IN THE PAN,
WE ADD GARLIC.
THROW IT RIGHT IN
LIKE THAT.
GOES STRAIGHT IN THERE.
WHOA. SOME OF THE SAUSAGE.
SAUSAGE THAT WE MADE,
BABY CLAMS, AND JUICE.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
THAT'S RIGHT. LITTLE BIT
OF BASIL AND OREGANO,
BLACK PEPPER.
COOK IT DOWN, SERVE IT ON
ANY PASTA WE WANT?
ANY PASTA YOU WANT.
WE'VE GOT RIGATONI HERE,
AND NOW WE ADD OUR
DOMERY SAUCE.
I DIDN'T ANTICIPATE
THE SAUSAGE WOULD BE GROUND UP
LIKE THAT.
DO YOU HEAR ME TRYING TO TALK?
MY MOUTH IS STARTING TO WATER.
MMM. OH, THAT MIGHT BE
ONE OF THE BEST WAYS
I'VE HAD RED CLAM SAUCE,
BECAUSE OF THAT SAUSAGE.
SO THE CLAMS ARE NICE
AND TENDER...
MM-HMM.
AND THEN, WOW.
BIG GARLIC BITE.
THAT ROCKS AND ROLLS.
I'M MAKING THIS WHEN I GET HOME.
MMM. NICE JOB.
RIGATONI DOMERY UP.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE DOMERY SAUCE?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
JUST MIXES VERY WELL--GARLIC,
THE CLAMS, AND THE SAUSAGE.
AND THEY'RE USING THAT SAME
SAUSAGE ON ANOTHER FAVORITE...
MAMA'S SPECIAL PIZZA--IT'S GOT
ABSOLUTELY EVERYTHING ON IT.
STARTING WITH A HOMEMADE
RED SAUCE AND HOMEMADE DOUGH.
WE PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL, CORNMEAL.
WE'VE GOT OUR PIZZA DOUGH.
LAY IT ON THE PAN.
MAKE LITTLE HOLES.
PLAYING THE PIZZA PIANO.
GOT OUR PIZZA SAUCE.
PEPPERONI DOWN FIRST?
THIS A CHEESE ON TOP
KIND OF JOINT?
YES, IT IS.
NOW OUR SAUSAGE.
THAT WE MADE.
FRESH MUSHROOMS, BLACK OLIVES,
ONIONS, BELL PEPPERS.
WOW, AT LEAST YOU DON'T
LOAD THIS THING UP.
NOW COMES OUR MOZZARELLA CHEESE,
A LITTLE OREGANO.
AND IN WE GO.
TAKES ABOUT EIGHT
TO TEN MINUTES.
WHEN IT'S ALMOST READY TO GO,
PULL THE PAN RIGHT OUT
AND LET IT SIT
ON TOP OF THE DECK.
NICE.
IT GETS A NICE CRUST ON IT.
GIVE IT A COUPLE OF MINUTES
LIKE THAT, CHECK THE BOTTOM
ONE LAST TIME...
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
AND COMES OUT OF THE OVEN.
THEN EIGHT PIECES,
AND THERE YOU GO.
YOU'VE GOT THE MAMA'S
SPECIAL PIZZA.
WOW, THAT THING'S HUGE.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD PIE, MAN.
LITTLE CRUNCH TO IT
WHEN YOU BITE INTO IT.
WHEN YOU'RE MAKING THE SAUCE
AND YOU'RE MAKING THE DOUGH,
YOU'RE MAKING THE SAUSAGE,
THAT'S REALLY THE FOUNDATION
OF GREAT PIZZA.
THAT'S JUST GOOD,
STRAIGHTFORWARD,
ALL-ITALIAN AMERICAN PIE.
THANK YOU.
MMM. NICE JOB.
APPRECIATE IT.
MAMA'S SPECIAL,
GOING UP.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
YOU ALWAYS KNOW YOU'RE GONNA
GET A GOOD PIZZA.
IT IS DELICIOUS--
THIS WHOLE PLACE.
MEATBALL,
MEAT SAUCE, UP.
TO ME, IT'S LIKE
AN EXTENSION OF MY HOME.
'CAUSE, HEY,
FRANK GREW UP HERE.
WHAT WAS YOUR
FIRST JOB?
ROLLING MEATBALLS,
EVER SINCE I WAS 5.
THEN WORKED HIS WAY
UP THE MENU.
GNOCCHI WITH MAMA SAUCE.
AND FINALLY ADDED A FEW
OF HIS OWN DISHES...
(woman) THE OSSO BUCCO.
CHICKEN PISANO
IN THE WINDOW.
CHICKEN PISANO IS FANTASTIC.
OH.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YOUR CHICKEN PARMESAN.
AT MAMA COZZA'S
IN ANAHEIM, CALIFORNIA...
LINGUINI VODKA,
GOING UP.
OWNERS FRANK COZZA...
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU
AGAIN.
AND FRANK JR...
VEAL PARM.
ARE SERVING UP 45 YEARS
OF FAMILY TRADITION.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
FAMILY HERE.
ALL THE COZZAS ARE HERE,
SISTERS, BROTHERS--
EVERYBODY HELPS OUT.
DOING WHAT THE FAMILY'S DONE
SINCE '65.
VEAL PARMESAN.
THANK YOU.
EVERYTHING THAT
MY GRANDMOTHER WOULD MAKE...
AND SOME FAVORITES HE INVENTED
HIMSELF, LIKE THIS ONE...
CHICKEN PISANO.
SAUSAGE, POTATOES,
CHICKEN, BROWN GRAVY.
THIS IS LIKE AN ITALIAN STEW.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
GOT A 10-INCH PAN,
A LITTLE BIT OF DRAWN BUTTER,
ADD OUR BELL PEPPERS,
JALAPEÑOS.
OH, GIVE IT SPICE.
THERE YOU GO.
DON'T TEASE ME.
SAUSAGE.
THIS IS A DIFFERENT SAUSAGE
THAN WE MADE, CORRECT?
YES, THIS IS FROM A VENDOR THAT
WE'VE BEEN DOING BUSINESS WITH
FOR A LONG TIME.
BEFORE YOU WERE IN CHARGE.
ADD THE POTATOES.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN IN CHARGE?
MY FATHER'S STILL HERE,
SO I'M NOT.
HE'S STILL RUNNING
THE SHOW?
HE STILL RUNS THE SHOW.
PUT THE CHICKEN ON THE GRILL.
WANT TO SEE SOMETHING COOL?
SEE THESE LITTLE STRIPES HERE?
THESE ARE SLICES
FROM A TENDERIZER.
YOU GUYS GOT YOUR OWN
IN-HOUSE TENDERIZER?
YES, WE DO.
PROBABLY ABOUT
A 50-YEAR-OLD HOBART.
THEY DROP THE CHICKEN
BREAST RIGHT THROUGH,
AND IT
TENDERIZES THE MEAT.
THAT'S AS CLOSE TO CHICKEN
SAUSAGE AS YOU'LL GET.
GIVE IT A LITTLE
QUICK FLIP, TAKE IT OUT.
NOW YOU GIVE IT
A LITTLE SLICE.
AND WE THROW IT
IN THE PAN.
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH THIS AT ALL.
STIR IT UP,
LET THE CHICKEN COOK.
A LITTLE BIT OF OREGANO
AND SWEET BASIL, BLACK PEPPER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE THICKENING ROUX,
ADDING A LITTLE FLOUR.
THE OIL THAT YOU HAVE FROM
THE BUTTER AND THE SAUSAGE
WORKS TOGETHER,
MAKES THE ROUX.
TURN THE HEAT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
GIVE IT A SHAKE, LET THE ROUX
BROWN JUST A LITTLE BIT.
WHAT KIND OF SAUCE
DOES THIS COME WITH?
THIS WILL BE
A BROWN GRAVY.
GIVE IT A SHOT OF SHERRY.
I LIKE WHERE
THAT'S GOING.
ADD OUR AU JUS
THAT WE MAKE.
SIMMER THIS FOR
ABOUT TWO MINUTES,
AND IT SHOULD
BE READY TO GO.
WHAT'S THIS GETTING
SERVED WITH?
TODAY WE'RE GONNA PUT
A SIDE OF BROCCOLI,
FETTUCCINE ALFREDO, AND WE'LL
GO AHEAD AND PLATE IT UP.
IT'S AN OLD-SCHOOL SAUCE,
RIGHT UP FRONT.
YES.
GOOD GRAVY. THE CHICKEN
IS JUST ABOUT FALL-APART TENDER.
LIKE THE POTATOES IN IT.
EVEN WITH THE JALAPEÑOS,
I DON'T THINK IT'S TOO SPICY.
WITH A LITTLE FETTUCCINE ALFREDO
ON THE SIDE, COOKED AL DENTE.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
ALFREDO?
YES.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S ITALIAN COMFORT FOOD.
GOOD STUFF.
(woman) CHICKEN PISANO.
THE BEST PISANO
I'VE EVER HAD.
NICE LITTLE KICK TO IT,
A LITTLE SPICE--
IT'S FANTASTIC, VERY GOOD.
(man) LASAGNA MAMA, UP.
I JUST LOVE THE FEELING
YOU GET COMING IN HERE.
HOW'S IT GOING
WITH YOU?
WHEN SOMEBODY COMES,
THEY ALWAYS WANT TO STAY.
IT'S THE COZZAS.
THEY REALLY DO GOOD STUFF HERE.
IF IT WASN'T FOR MY KIDS,
IT WOULDN'T BE POSSIBLE.
THAT'S GREAT
FOR YOU TO SAY.
REALLY NICE TO MEET YOU.
YOU GUYS ARE AWESOME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SIR, THANK YOU.
SO I TOLD YOU, IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
UH, THAT'S WHERE
YOU LOST IT, RIGHT THERE.
(laughter)