HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU WROTE IN
AND TOLD ME TO COME HERE?
I DID.
YOU FOUND 'EM.
ANYTHING YOU ORDER...
MEATLOAF UP.
IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
IN LEXINGTON, KENTUCKY...
CHILI DOG, PLEASE.
AN ORIGINAL DRIVE-IN...
"POOR BOY" WITH TATER TOTS.
SERVIN' UP FAVORITES...
MY FOLKS USED TO BRING ME HERE
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
FROM THE '50s.
"POOR BOY," RINGS.
IT'S SO GOOD,
I TOOK A HUGE BITE.
(mumbles)
IN JACKSONVILLE...
PANCAKES BANANA GRANOLA.
THIS IS PHENOMENAL FOOD.
THE LOCAL DINER...
EVERYTHING HERE IS DELICIOUS.
DOIN' LOADED...
YO HALA.
DINER FAVORITES.
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
AND, HEY...
(woman) PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD.
YOU WANT FRIES WITH THAT?
MMM.
THAT'S A SALAD.
OH, YEAH.
YEAH.
AND IN MINNEAPOLIS...
SHORT STACK!
WE'RE CELEBRATING
THE 60th ANNIVERSARY...
THIS IS THE NUMBER ONE PLACE
TO GO.
OF A TRIPLE "D" ORIGINAL.
I GOT A PICKUP DOWN HERE!
DOUG'S GOT ISSUES, YEAH.
THAT'S WHY WE LIKE HIM.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
IN LEXINGTON, KENTUCKY.
NOW I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
YOU'RE THINKING HORSES, BOURBON,
AND THE U.K. WILDCATS.
BUT IF YOU'RE FROM HERE,
YOU'D ALSO ADD TO THAT LIST
A 58-YEAR-OLD, 75-BAY DRIVE-IN
HERE ON NEW CIRCLE ROAD.
THAT'S FAMOUS
FOR THEIR FRIED CHICKEN
AND THEIR "POOR BOYS."
YOU GOT IT. I'M TALKING
ABOUT THE PARKETTE DRIVE-IN.
THANK YOU FOR CHOOSING PARKETTE.
MAY I TAKE YOUR ORDER, PLEASE?
I WILL HAVE A "POOR BOY."
(Guy) THEY RUN IT OUT TO YOU?
YES, SIR.
THE OLD-SCHOOL WAY.
"POOR BOY" WITH TATER TOTS.
(man) Welcome to Parkette.
CAN I TAKE YOUR ORDER,
PLEASE?
I'D LIKE A CHICKEN BOX.
WE USED TO COME HERE, A BUNCH
OF GUYS AND GALS, YOU KNOW,
JUST HANGIN' OUT.
HOW LONG YOU GIRLS
BEEN COMING HERE?
OH, MY GOSH, IT STARTED
WHEN I WAS A KID.
WE ALWAYS CAME INSIDE.
MY FOLKS USED TO BRING ME HERE
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE GIRL,
SO I GREW UP
EATING PARKETTE.
BUT THREE YEARS AGO, THIS PLACE
WAS ALL BUT BOARDED UP.
THEN...
IT HIT THE STREETS
THAT I WAS COMING BACK.
I WAS DELIGHTED.
THANKS TO JEFF KAPLAN...
BANANA SPLIT.
AND HIS BROTHER RANDY...
FISH IS COMING RIGHT NOW.
WHO BOUGHT THE JOINT,
'CAUSE THEY COULDN'T LET
A LEGEND DIE.
WE WANTED TO BRING IT
BACK TO GLORY.
BRING IT BACK
TO ITS HEYDAY.
LIKE IT USED TO BE
BACK IN THE '50s
WHEN JOE SMILEY
FIRST OPENED THE PLACE.
HIS NAME WAS JOE SMILEY?
JOE SMILEY.
AND TODAY...
CHILI DOG JUMBO.
THEY'RE KEEPING
THE JOE SMILEY CLASSICS COMING.
CHOCOLATE SHAKE.
YOU JUST GOT TO KEEP IT
OLD SCHOOL.
CHICKEN GIZZARD BOX.
"POOR BOY," RINGS.
NUMBER ONE SELLER
ON THE MENU?
"POOR BOY."
THE "POOR BOY" SANDWICH.
(woman) IT'S A BIG CHEESEBURGER
WITH LOTS OF TOPPINGS.
IT'S GREAT.
THERE'S YOUR "POOR BOY."
THANK YOU. THAT'S THE ONLY THING
MY DAD WILL EVER EAT
IS A "POOR BOY"
WITH TATER TOTS.
IT'S NOT A PO'BOY.
THAT IS CORRECT.
IT'S THE "POOR BOY."
JOE SMILEY CAME UP
WITH THIS CONCEPT.
"POOR BOY" IS YEARS
BEFORE THE BIG MAC.
NO KIDDING.
YES.
WHAT ARE WE
HITTIN' IT WITH?
A LITTLE SEASON MIX.
THOSE ARE GONNA COOK FAST.
AS SOON AS IT TURNS A LITTLE
BROWN AROUND THE RING,
THAT'S WHEN YOU KNOW
IT'S READY TO GO.
FRESH, NEVER FROZEN.
SEE, I LOVE BURGERS
ON A FLATTOP.
GET THAT LITTLE CRUST
TO THEM--MMM.
YES.
WE READY TO GO?
WE'RE READY.
SO WE TOAST A BUN AND THEN...
PARKETTE SAUCE.
FORTIFIED MAYONNAISE?
THAT'S RIGHT. AND LETTUCE,
PATTY NUMBER ONE,
MIDDLE BUN, MUSTARD,
CHEESE...
SLAB OF CHEESE.
SECOND PATTY,
BIG SLAB OF ONION...
WHOA.
TOMATO, PICKLE, TOP BUN.
THROW A FRILL IN THERE.
THAT IS THE FAMOUS
KENTUCKY "POOR BOY."
HOW MUCH IS THIS BAD BOY?
$3.29.
SERIOUSLY?
IT'S SO GOOD,
I TOOK A HUGE BITE.
THAT'S ALL THE STUFF
I LIKE IN A GOOD BURGER.
THE PATTY'S FRESH--
A LITTLE SEASONING.
IT'S GOT A NICE BUN ON IT.
SOMETIMES THE SIMPLE THINGS
ARE WHAT MAKE IT WORK.
IT'S A GOOD OLD-SCHOOL BURGER.
FOR $3 AND A QUARTER--
YOU'RE GIVING IT AWAY.
HERE'S YOUR "POOR BOYS"
WITH FRIES.
GOOD OLD ALL-AMERICAN
CHEESEBURGER--CAN'T BEAT IT.
HERE'S A "POOR BOY"
AND FRIES.
IT'S JUST A GREAT BURGER.
THAT'S ALL I CAN REALLY SAY.
IT'S JUST REALLY GOOD.
GET AFTER THAT!
THAT'S A "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" BITE RIGHT THERE.
IT'S NICE.
WITH ALL THE FAST FOOD CHAINS,
THEY'RE ACTUALLY
MAKING IT THERE.
REGULAR "POOR BOY."
JUST SIT IN MY CAR AND RELAX--
IT'S A UNIQUE EXPERIENCE.
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
SO WHY DO YOU THINK
PEOPLE LIKE DRIVE-INS?
I THINK IT'S JUST BECAUSE
OF THE NOSTALGIA.
THIS IS WHAT IT WAS LIKE
WHEN I WAS A KID.
FISHERMAN'S SPECIAL.
THE MEMORIES
REALLY KEPT ME COMING BACK.
SAME ATMOSPHERE, THOUGH--
IT'S WONDERFUL.
(laughter)
THIS IS A PIECE OF AMERICANA.
IT'S A PIECE OF LEXINGTON.
HERE'S YOUR HALF WHITE.
IT'S THE VINTAGE ATMOSPHERE.
Y'ALL ENJOY.
IT JUST TAKES YOU BACK
TO A SIMPLER TIME.
TWO FRIES
AND A CHOCOLATE SHAKE.
IS THAT ALL FOR YOU?
(man) Yeah, that's all.
FRIED BOLOGNA.
(man) THE FOOD'S
STILL THE BEST.
STILL WHAT YOU LOVE.
YEAH.
AND STILL FROM
ALL THE DRIVE-IN FOOD GROUPS...
DOUBLE CHEESE.
FROM DEEP-FRIED FAVORITES...
TICKET'S UP--RINGS.
CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF 'EM.
TATER TOTS.
LOVE THE TATER TOTS.
CLASSIC DESSERTS...
BANANA SPLITS--AWESOME.
AND OF COURSE, THE DOG...
DOGS ARE READY.
SMOTHERED IN A JOE SMILEY
TRADITION.
THE ORIGINAL
HOT DOG CHILI SAUCE.
IT'S NOT CHILI.
IT'S HOT DOG CHILI SAUCE.
YES.
CHILI POWDER, PAPRIKA.
WE'RE GONNA ADD CUMIN,
GARLIC POWDER,
AND THE CAYENNE.
ANY SALT GOING INTO THIS?
NO. NO SALT.
NO SALT IN THE CHILI?
THE WAY WE PREPARE IT WITH
MUSTARD, ONION, AND THE HOT DOG,
IT EXPLODES IN THE FLAVOR.
AS A CHILI,
IT'S NOT THE BEST-TASTING.
OKAY, SO MIX IT UP, AND THEN
LOW AND SLOW COOK IT DOWN?
THAT'S IT.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA
PUT IN OIL.
THEN WE JUST ADD OUR MEAT.
80/20?
YES. PUT SOME ONIONS ON IT.
AND WATER. IT'S INTERESTING.
SIMPLE BEAUTY.
MEAT'S COOKED DOWN.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
WE'LL ADD OUR DRY SPICES
RIGHT NOW.
A LOT OF PAPRIKA,
GARLIC, AND NO...
SALT.
AND THIS IS HOW JOE MADE IT.
THIS IS HOW JOE MADE IT.
OKAY, SO LET'S GIVE HER
A LITTLE TASTE.
THAT NEEDS SOME HELP.
TO MAKE IT
A LITTLE MORE PALATABLE...
KETCHUP IS GONNA MAKE
A DIFFERENCE?
COME ON.
AT LEAST WE'RE GONNA GET SOME
SUGAR AND SOME SALT IN THERE.
JUST ENOUGH TO TAKE
A LITTLE BITE OF THE BITE OUT.
SO NOW SHE'S READY TO GO?
THAT'S IT.
A HUNDRED TIMES BETTER.
STILL COULD USE A LITTLE SALT,
BUT YOU SAY THAT
THAT DOG AND EVERYTHING'S
GONNA CARRY IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
TIME TO MAKE THE CHILI DOG.
LET'S GO, BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT.
DO WE SKIM THE OIL
OFF THAT?
NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT!
JOE ALWAYS SAID THAT
THAT KEEPS THE FLAVOR IN.
OKAY, HOW DO YOU BUILD ONE?
STEAMED BUN?
STEAMED BUN.
STEAMED DOG.
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSTARD.
A LITTLE BIT?
FOR ME, THAT'S A LITTLE.
COMIN' IN HOT--
CHILI SAUCE.
CAN SEE THAT OIL
ON TOP OF THAT.
YES. CHOPPED ONION.
NOW WE CAN DO SHREDDED CHEESE
ON THERE IF YOU'D LIKE.
HIT THE CHEESE.
THAT'S THE DOG.
WOW. ALL RIGHT,
HERE WE GO.
IS IT GETTING ON ME?
I'VE HAD A FEW DOGS IN MY DAY
FROM CHICAGO TO NEW YORK.
DID IT ALL RIGHT--BUN'S STEAMED,
DOG'S GOT SNAP,
ONIONS ARE DICED
TO THE RIGHT SIZE.
I MEAN, YOU DID
ALL THE PIECES, MAN.
WHEN YOU'RE INCORPORATING
THE SALTINESS OF THE DOG,
THE BITE OF THE ONION, THE HALF
GALLON OF MUSTARD YOU PUT ON,
IF YOU HAD ANY MORE SALT
IN THAT CHILI SAUCE,
IT WOULD BE TOO MUCH.
THAT'S AUTHENTIC. NICE JOB.
CHILI DOG, PLEASE.
I LOVE CHILI. I LOVE HOT DOGS.
I LOVE CHEESE. IT'S JUST GOOD.
CHILI DOG WITH CHEESE.
YOU DON'T WANT TO STOP EATING.
IT'S JUST REALLY GOOD FOOD.
"POOR BOY," PLEASE, TINA.
COMING.
JUST GOOD SOUTHERN COOKIN'.
SWING IN, GET A BURGER,
GET A LITTLE FRIED CHICKEN.
I NEED EXTRA GRAVY.
MY FAVORITE THING ON THE MENU
IS THEIR FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S FRIED PERFECTLY.
THE REAL KENTUCKY WAY.
PORK LARD--
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
YES, THE ONLY WAY
TO DO IT.
LARD.
I'M GONNA CUT IT UP FIRST.
PUT TWO CUBES IN THERE.
GET IT PACKED UNDER THE COILS
AND WE'LL MELT IT.
(humming)
(Austrian accent) FIRST
HE PUSHES DOWN THE LARD.
HE'S WORKING OUT.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT
THE THIRD ONE IN.
(normal voice) 'CAUSE THAT
HOT OIL'S GONNA START MELTING
EVERYTHING ON TOP. KIND OF
LIKE THE ICEBERG IS SINKING.
YES.
ALL RIGHT SO THIS GOES DOWN,
AND THEN WE CAN START
DOING SOME CHICKEN.
SO THIS
IS THE BREADING PROCESS?
YES. WE'LL PUT
THE EGGS IN FIRST, SALT.
PEPPER,
SEASONING MIXTURE...
YES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD MILK.
BUTTERMILK?
JUST REGULAR MILK.
REGULAR MILK?
YES.
YOU'LL BATTER AND DROP.
YOU DON'T LET IT SIT UP FOR 20
MINUTES OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
NO.
LET'S SEE IT.
DROP IN THE BATTER, MAKE SURE
THAT YOU HAVE ALL THE GOODNESS.
DROP IT IN THE FLOUR,
STRAIGHT TO FRYER.
300-DEGREE OIL--
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE TO COOK?
WE'LL DROP IT FOR 20.
IT'LL BE BEAUTIFUL.
IN LARD.
THAT'S IT.
HOW DOES IT GET SERVED UP?
PUT IT IN A BOX
WITH GRAVY, SLAW, A ROLL,
CHOICE OF FRIES,
TOTS, OR RINGS.
OKAY. IT'S ABOUT
8 MILLION DEGREES.
GREAT FLAVOR, NOT TOO HEAVY,
ALMOST REMINDS ME A LITTLE BIT
OF KIND OF A ROASTED CHICKEN,
WHERE IT'S GOT A THIN,
CRUNCHY CRUST ON IT,
BUT A LOT OF SEASONING.
THE CHICKEN'S SUPER MOIST.
YOU CAN ALSO DIP
YOUR CHICKEN IN THE GRAVY.
MMM.
GOOD PEPPER IN THE GRAVY--
THAT'S WHAT I'M DIGGIN'.
IT'S LIKE CHICKEN-FRIED STEAK.
GREAT STUFF.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, BRO.
HERE'S YOUR FOURTH WHITE
WITH FRIES.
REALLY JUICY AND TENDER
ON THE INSIDE.
PERFECTLY SEASONED.
QUARTER WHITE, FRIES.
IT'S THE BEST.
HOT AND JUICY AND CRISPY
AND PRETTY DELICIOUS.
ONE "POOR BOY," PLEASE.
THE FOOD IS PHENOMENAL.
WE JUST CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF IT.
DOUBLE BACON CHEESEBURGER.
IT'S JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO HANG OUT.
CHILI DOG TO GO.
THE FACT THAT YOU WROTE IN
AND TOLD US ABOUT THIS,
THIS IS HOW WE FIND
THE GREAT PLACES.
"POOR BOY" WITH FRIES.
IT'S VINTAGE. IT'S NOSTALGIC.
IT'S PART OF MY PAST--
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
CONGRATULATIONS FOR DOING IT
THE RIGHT WAY AND REBUILDING IT,
PUTTING IT BACK
TO ITS GLORY DAYS,
BECAUSE THIS PLACE
IS ROCKIN' AND ROLLIN'.
JUMBO CHICAGO WITH RINGS.
AND YOU'RE KEEPING THE FOOD
LEGIT, SO GOOD JOB.
APPRECIATE IT.
THANKS, GUYS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
UP NEXT...
YOU GUYS ENJOY.
WE'RE HEADING
TO JACKSONVILLE...
THEY COOK EVERYTHING
FRESH DAILY.
TO LIGHTEN THINGS UP
WITH A SALAD...
THE COOL, CRISP LETTUCE,
THEN YOU GET A CRUNCHY,
SALTY FRENCH FRY.
MMM. THAT'S A NEW DEFINITION
OF SALAD.
I'M HERE
IN THE SAN MARCO NEIGHBORHOOD
OF JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA,
JUST A FEW MILES FROM DOWNTOWN.
NOW I KNOW WHEN YOU ROLL
INTO A COASTAL TOWN
LIKE JACKSONVILLE, WELL, YOU'RE
EXPECTING TO FIND SEAFOOD.
BUT IN THIS TOWN,
THERE'S A LOT MORE THAN THAT.
AND AS THE NAME
OF THE SHOW GOES,
IT'S
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
AND THIS IS METRO DINER.
PANCAKES BANANA GRANOLA.
THIS IS PHENOMENAL FOOD.
THEY COOK
EVERYTHING FRESH DAILY.
STUFFED PORTOBELLO SANDWICH
UP.
OUR FIRST TIME HERE,
WE LOOKED AT EACH OTHER
AND SAID, "THIS SHOULD
BE ON GUY'S SHOW."
SO YOU WROTE IN
AND TOLD ME TO COME HERE?
I DID.
I WROTE IN,
BECAUSE I BRING PEOPLE HERE
EVERY TIME
THEY COME INTO TOWN.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME,
ANYTHING YOU ORDER.
PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD UP.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
REAL GOOD FOOD--HE ACTUALLY
COOKS EVERYTHING FRESH.
PASTRAMI SANDWICH UP--
RUNNER, PLEASE.
IT'S JUST
A REALLY GREAT DINER.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU GUYS ENJOY.
WHEN I WALKED IN HERE
THE FIRST TIME,
I JUST FELL IN LOVE
WITH THE PLACE.
SO CHEF MARK DAVOLI...
TWO EGGS AND GRITS.
BOUGHT THE JOINT.
I NEED A RUNNER, PLEASE.
THEN TALKED HIS DAD JOHN...
OKAY, HERE WE GO, FELLAS.
A CORPORATE RESTAURANT VET
INTO JOINING HIM.
HOW IS IT?
(Mark) HE HANDLES
THE FRONT OF THE HOUSE.
(Guy) HE'S THE AMBASSADOR?
YEP, YEP.
(John) ALL RIGHT, THANKS.
YOU MANAGE THE KITCHEN.
I DO THE KITCHEN, YEAH.
METRO MELT, MEDIUM.
IT'S HOME COOKING.
MEATLOAF UP.
THE MEATLOAF
IS UNBELIEVABLE HERE.
(Guy) NOW IS MEATLOAF
A STAPLE ON THE MENU?
IT IS DEFINITELY A STAPLE.
OKAY, SO GET IT GOING.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL START
WITH THE CARROTS.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND THEM.
THIS WILL BREAK IT DOWN
TO THE SIZE
THAT IT CAN BE COOKED
ALL THE WAY THROUGH,
BUT NOT BE
A BIG INTRUSIVE CHUNK.
YEAH, THAT--
INTRUSIVE CHUNK.
OKAY?
WITHOUT A DOUBT.
THAT'S A TERM
YOU USE OFTEN?
YEAH.
"YOU KNOW WHAT? COME ON DOWN FOR
OUR MEATLOAF HERE AT METRO,
UH, NO INTRUSIVE CHUNKS."
CELERY.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND 'EM.
GET THOSE
TO THE OPTIMUM SIZE.
YEP.
THE MUSHROOMS.
MUSHROOMS
VERY GINGERLY DONE.
JUST MUSHROOMS, NOT GINGER,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I MEANT.
NOW YOU DO THE ONIONS.
YEAH. YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND THEM.
ALL RIGHT, SO THIS
IS ALL READY TO GO
WITH THIS NICE VEGGIE MIX
AND THIS BRAND-NEW BOWL.
THAT'S BEEN HERE,
OH, 20 YEARS AT LEAST,
WOULD BE MY GUESS.
YES, IT--YEP,
IT'S CARBON-DATED A.D.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE GOT SOME--
THE MEAT TRIO.
YEP.
GROUND BEEF...
PORK?
AND PORK...
HAVE TO.
AND GROUND TURKEY.
THAT'S THE WAY
TO GET HEALTHY WITH IT.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, SO YOU INCORPORATE
ALL THE MEATS.
YEAH.
READY? THERE YOU GO.
BEAUTIFUL.
I LIKE THE VEGGIE CONTENT.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, SO WHAT DO WE GOT
FOR SEASONINGS?
PEPPER, SALT,
AND WORCESTERSHIRE.
I WAS GONNA SAY, THERE'S GOT
TO BE SOME WORCESTERSHIRE.
GET A GOOD MIX GOING.
ANYTHING ELSE
WE'RE INCORPORATING?
WHAT ABOUT A BINDER?
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT OF EGG.
OKAY. BREADCRUMBS?
YEAH, BREADCRUMBS.
I LIKE THIS.
YEAH.
SO YOU FORM UP THE LOGS...
THREE OUT ON A TRAY...
YEAH.
BAKE IT OFF AT 350...
FOR?
40 MINUTES.
BRING IT OUT, LET IT COOL.
LOOK AT THAT.
MM-HMM.
IT'S LIKE A SPEED BUMP
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
HOW DO YOU JUST KEEP FROM
PICKING INTO IT RIGHT NOW?
IT'S HARD.
OH, YOU GOT PEOPLE
AT THE FRONT DOOR.
(laughs)
THAT WAS A GOOD ONE.
IT'S GREAT.
I SHOULD HAVE
SAW THAT COMING.
SO TWO BIG SLICES
OVER TO THE FLATTOP.
YEP.
PUT A LITTLE MARGARINE DOWN,
PUT THE MEATLOAF ON--
ABOUT TWO, THREE MINUTES
EACH SIDE.
THIS IS THE ART
OF "CRUSTIFICATION."
UH-HUH.
AND THEN
WHAT DO WE SERVE IT WITH?
MASHED POTATOES, ZUCCHINI,
AND SQUASH
AND A LITTLE FRENCH BAGUETTE.
IT'S JUST WHAT YOU'D EXPECT
IN A DINER.
THAT'S A BIG PORTION.
YEAH.
MMM.
I THINK
DINERS ACROSS THE WORLD
HAVE TO TAKE A LESSON
ON THIS ONE--
TENDER, JUICY,
GOOD EXTERIOR CRUST--MMM.
BUT IF THE "CRUNCHIFICATION,"
THE ADDING THAT EXTRA LAYER,
ALL THAT LITTLE CRUNCH
ON THE SIDE...
MMM.
AND WHY DO YOU EVEN
MESS UP THE PLATE
WITH VEGETABLES AND BREAD?
I JUST WOULD LIKE A--I'D LIKE
YOU TO FLOAT THAT IN GRAVY.
THE MEATLOAF PLATE.
THAT WAS REALLY GOOD--THE SPICES
AND THE GRAVY ON TOP.
IT'S VERY SAVORY AND VERY MOIST.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
FILL-YOUR-STOMACH MEAL.
OF COURSE,
YOU CAN GET A SALAD...
THE PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD
IS HUMUNGOUS.
WITH FRIES AND A STEAK.
EVERYTHING YOU WANT
IS IN THIS SALAD.
PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD?
A TRADITION BACK IN PITTSBURGH
WHERE MARK GREW UP.
WE START WITH PRIME RIB?
YEAH. KIND OF LIKE
ONE OF THE SALADS
YOU CAN GO HOME
AND TELL YOUR WIFE.
"WHAT DID YOU HAVE
FOR LUNCH TODAY?"
"OH, I WAS DOWN AT METRO DINER.
I HAD--I HAD A SALAD...
WITH A BIG SLAB
OF PRIME RIB ON IT."
HOW MANY OUNCES?
UH, ABOUT 6 TO 7 OUNCES.
YEAH, SO LIGHT.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW,
REAL LIGHT DIET SALAD.
RIGHT, YEAH, YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE MARBLING. CHOICE?
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
YEP, YEP.
CHOICE.
WHY WOULD YOU PUT
ANYTHING ELSE ON YOUR SALAD?
ALL RIGHT, NOW...
THE MARGARINE.
OF COURSE THE MARGARINE.
YEAH.
DO YOU BUY THAT
IN THE 50-GALLON DRUM?
STEAK DOWN, SEASON IT--
SALT AND PEPPER.
NOW WHAT'S NEXT?
DROP THE FRENCH FRIES.
FOR THE SALAD?
FOR THE SALAD.
MY KIND OF SALAD.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BLUE CHEESE DRESSING.
SOUR CREAM.
OKAY.
MAYONNAISE.
BUTTERMILK?
YEAH, BUTTERMILK.
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA WHISK IT.
OKAY.
ADD BLUE CHEESE CRUMBLES.
THAT'S A MONSTER BLUE CHEESE.
UH-HUH. FOLD THAT IN.
SO THE DRESSING'S DONE.
YEP.
GRAB THE STEAK.
YEP. CUT THE STEAK.
OKAY.
GONNA PUT SOME FRIES
ON IT.
SERIOUSLY,
THAT MANY FRIES?
STEAK GOES
ON TOP OF THAT.
YOU'RE HEARD
OF JENNY CRAIG.
THIS IS HER BROTHER
JERRY CRAIG.
WE PUT THE BLUE CHEESE CRUMBLES
ON THERE.
OH, AND CROUTONS.
YEAH, WHY WOULDN'T YOU?
DON'T TELL ME YOU'RE PUTTING
DRESSING ON THE SIDE.
WE PUT IT ON THE SIDE.
MEN OF AMERICA
ARE UNITING RIGHT NOW
IN THEIR TOWNS AND CITIES
AND LOADING BUSES,
ON THEIR WAY DOWN
TO METRO DINER,
JUST BECAUSE THEY'LL BE ABLE
TO SAY, "BUT IT WAS A SALAD."
I DON'T EVEN
HAVE ENOUGH FORK.
MMM.
OH, YEAH.
YEAH.
THAT'S A SALAD.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
STEAK IS MEGA SUPER TENDER.
YOU GET THE COOL,
CRISP LETTUCE--MMM--
THE NICE TANGY DRESSING,
THEN YOU GET A CRUNCHY,
SALTY FRENCH FRY.
DON'T FIND THAT EVERY DAY
ON A SALAD.
THAT'S THE NEW DEFINITION
OF SALAD.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
YOUR MOM USED TO MAKE THIS?
YEAH.
SURPRISED YOU GUYS COULD EVEN
WALK OUT OF THE HOUSE.
PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD UP.
THAT HIT OF BLUE CHEESE
WITH THAT RIB EYE ON TOP
IS SO DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING YOU WANT IS
IN THIS SALAD. IT'S PERFECT.
I WOULD EAT A LOT MORE SALADS
IF THEY ALL CAME--
IF THEY CAME LIKE THIS.
YES.
PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD UP.
CALLING THIS A SALAD
IS LIKE CALLING MY
DIESEL FOUR-WHEEL DRIVE
LIFTED 4-DOOR CREW CAB
YELLOW MONSTER TRUCK
A COMMUTER CAR.
NOT YOUR TYPICAL SALAD...
OH.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
NOT YOUR TYPICAL DINER.
AND THIS AIN'T
YOUR TYPICAL BREAKFAST...
OH, DUDE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
GOT AN OMELET WALKING IN.
(Mark) BREAKFAST PIE RUNNER,
PLEASE.
IN JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA...
PITTSBURGH STEAK SALAD UP.
FOLKS ARE PACKING
INTO THE METRO DINER...
TWO "SCRAM" WITH CHEESE.
AND STARTIN' EARLY...
THE BREAKFASTS HERE
ARE JUST SO WONDERFUL.
PANCAKE UP.
OH, MY GOSH, THE PANCAKES
ARE AMAZING.
SAN FRANCISCO EGGS BENEDICT.
BREAKFAST PIE WITH HASH BROWNS
UP.
ALL CRANKED OUT
BY OWNER MARK DAVOLI...
CINNAMON RAISIN FRENCH TOAST UP.
RUNNER, PLEASE.
IT'S REALLY PHENOMENAL.
FROM EGGS BENEDICT...
SURF & TURF EGG BENNY UP.
UNBELIEVABLE.
TO SHRIMP AND GRITS...
IT'S THE BEST SHRIMP AND GRITS--
INCREDIBLE.
AND THIS E-MAIL FAVORITE.
WHY'D YOU WRITE IN?
THE YO HALA--
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
YO HALA.
STUFFED FRENCH TOAST.
WE CALL IT
THE YO HALA ON THE SQUARE.
THAT'S CHALLAH BREAD
FRENCH TOAST...
(woman) STUFFED
WITH CREAM CHEESE...
GONE WILD.
SERVED WITH BLUEBERRY COMPOTE
AND STRAWBERRIES ON TOP--
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
WHY DO YOU HOLD YOUR HANDS LIKE
THIS WHEN YOU TELL ME ABOUT IT?
BECAUSE IT'S ABOUT AS BIG
AS YOUR HEAD.
OKAY.
LITTLE BIT OF MARGARINE.
MARGARINE.
WE TAKE BANANAS,
THROW THEM IN THE POT.
JUST WANT
TO GET THEM ACTIVATED.
YOU'RE GONNA ACTIVATE
YOUR BANANAS?
(laughing) WHAT--
WHAT CULINARY--
WHAT CULINARY POSITION
IS BANANA ACTIVATION?
ADD A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR.
OKAY.
GIVE A LITTLE STIR.
HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE FRANGELICA.
NICE.
SO YOU'VE ACTIVATED
THE BANANAS.
WE WANT TO TAKE
OUR CREAM CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA FOLD THE BANANA
MIXTURE INTO THE CREAM CHEESE.
OKAY, WHAT'S NEXT
IN THIS HALA?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A BLUEBERRY-STRAWBERRY COMPOTE.
BLUEBERRIES,
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER...
OKAY.
NOW GOES IN THE BROWN SUGAR.
SO THE SLURRY GOES IN?
YEP, CORNSTARCH SLURRY
JUST TO TIGHTEN THAT UP,
AND THEN I PUT
THE STRAWBERRIES IN LAST.
IF YOU PUT THE STRAWBERRIES
IN TOO EARLY, THEY BREAK UP.
STRAWBERRIES GO IN.
LET THAT COOK DOWN KIND OF
UNTIL IT ALL BREAKS DOWN...
YEP.
THICKENS UP, AND THAT'S GONNA
GO ON TOP OF THE--
HOLY CHALLAH.
WOW.
YOU KNOW, TRADITIONAL CHALLAH
IS NORMALLY A LITTLE FLATTER,
BUT I HAD TO GET MY BAKER
TO CHANGE IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S LIKE THE DANCING TOOTH
FROM SATURDAY MORNING CARTOONS.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
OUR BANANA MIXTURE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
YEAH.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THAT NOW?
NOW WE'RE GONNA DUMP IT
INTO OUR EGG WASH,
WHICH IS EGG, CINNAMON,
NUTMEG, VANILLA, SUGAR, CREAM.
MARGARINE.
NECESSARY, OF COURSE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA--WE'RE GONNA
GRILL UP ALL SIDES.
ALL THE SIDES.
YEAH. THE TOAST IS DONE.
THERE YOU ARE.
THAT'S NICE.
AND WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH THE BLUEBERRY-STRAWBERRY
COMPOTE.
PLEASE TELL ME WE'RE GONNA
COAT THIS WITH POWDERED SUGAR
AND COTTON CANDY.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
A LITTLE POWDERED SUGAR.
(chuckles)
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
I WAS JOKING!
THAT, DUDE,
IS OUT OF CONTROL.
YOU GOTTA
JUST KIND OF DIVE IN.
OH, DUDE.
THAT'S MORE FRENCH TOAST
THAN I'VE EATEN
IN THE LAST TEN YEARS--
ONE BITE WAS.
ONE BITE.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT THIS,
SERIOUSLY--NO KIDDING.
THE CHALLAH
HAS FANTASTIC TEXTURE.
THE CREAM CHEESE--SMOOTH,
WORKS THE BANANA,
NOT OVERLY SWEET,
BUT IT'S THE ACIDITY
IN THE BLUEBERRIES
FROM THE COMPOTE
THAT REALLY KIND OF ADDS
THAT CONTRAST OF THE SOUR,
OF THE--DUDE,
THAT IS WORTH COMING HERE FOR.
NO QUESTION.
YO HALA UP.
THE SWEETNESS AND THE FRESHNESS
OF THE BLUEBERRIES
AND THE CHALLAH BREAD,
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
HOW MUCH OF THE HALA
CAN YOU ENJOY?
MAYBE A QUARTER.
CAN YOU
TAKE THE HALA HOME?
OH, I TAKE THE HALA HOME.
IF IT'S HALF A CHALLAH,
DO YOU HELP CHALLAH
HALF A HALA HOME?
I HELP CHALLAH HALF
A HALA HOME IF I CAN.
(woman laughs)
EVERYTHING HERE
IS DELICIOUS.
EGGS BENEDICT.
YOU HAVE TO COME TO THE METRO
WITH A BIG APPETITE.
APPRECIATE YOU
HIGHLIGHTING IT FOR US.
DEFINITELY WORTH STOPPING AT.
GOOD.
IT'S A GREAT TIME. IT'S A GREAT
PLACE. GOOD JOB, GUYS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
VERY NICE, SIR.
(applause)
NEXT UP...
COME ON DOWN!
WE'RE HEADING TO MINNEAPOLIS.
I GOT A PICKUP DOWN HERE!
TO ANSWER
THE AGE-OLD QUESTION...
WOULD YOU CALL THIS PLACE
A DUMP OR A DIVE?
DIVE.
THAT'S ONE VOTE
FOR DIVE.
DEFINITELY A DIVE.
DIVE.
THAT'S TWO.
ON OUR FIRST
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
WE VISITED A FUNKY LITTLE PLACE
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA.
THEN IT WAS
A POPULAR BREAKFAST JOINT.
NOW TAKE A LOOK.
TODAY, THEY'RE CELEBRATING
THEIR 60th ANNIVERSARY.
THIS IS AL'S BREAKFAST.
THIS PLACE HAS BEEN HERE
FOR 60 YEARS.
DID IT CHANGE AT ALL?
NO.
NO?
NO, IT REALLY HASN'T.
YEP, STILL PACKED...
COME ON DOWN.
I'M GETTIN' US A TABLE.
JUST HANG ON A SECOND.
STILL WORTH THE WAIT...
USUALLY AT LEAST 30 MINUTES.
AND STILL RUN BY
THE KING OF THE JOINT...
MARY ROSE, GET DOWN HERE!
DOUG GRINA.
(Mary Rose) I'M BUSY!
YOU'RE GONNA GET BUSIER!
DOUG'S GOT ISSUES, YEAH.
THAT'S WHY WE LIKE HIM.
SHORT STACK!
I GOT A PICKUP DOWN HERE!
YOUR 60th ANNIVERSARY--
NOTHING'S CHANGED.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
WELL, YOU'VE UPGRADED
TO iTouch.
WELL, WE'RE REALLY WITH IT
WITH TECHNOLOGY HERE.
YEAH, YOU ARE.
AND WE ENLARGED--WE TOOK
THE WALL BOARD OFF THAT SIDE.
IT'S 3/4 OF AN INCH.
I DIDN'T NOTICE THE BRICK.
COME ON DOWN--
EXTRA SEATING.
THE PAYMENT BOOKS
ARE STILL HERE.
PEOPLE JUST LAY DOWN
THEIR MONEY.
YOU START WITH YOUR BALANCE.
YEP.
AND YOU JUST START DOING
THE DEDUCTION AND THEN ADD MORE.
YEP.
CAREFULLY ALPHABETIZED.
NO, I LIKE THE WAY
YOU DO IT.
ANYBODY WILL A BOOK?
LEGACY BOOKS--GOOD IDEA, GUY!
I GOT A DELINQUENT FRENCH TOAST
HERE.
LET ME--
I ALSO NEED EGGS
IN ONE ORDER.
DOES HE HAVE A TIARA ON?
YES.
IT HASN'T CHANGED.
AND NEITHER HAVE THE REGULARS
LIKE NICK BENSON.
YOU EAT THE SAME THING
EVERY TIME, DON'T YOU?
JUST ABOUT.
CAN I PUT MY BREAKFAST
ON HERE?
OH, YEAH.
YOU'VE BEEN COMING HERE
PROBABLY LONGER THAN MOST.
SINCE 1959.
THE PLACE IS A LOT WIDER NOW.
'CAUSE THEY TOOK OFF
THE FIBERBOARD
THAT WAS FALLING DOWN.
RIGHT, PAINTED IT
WITH A BRIGHTER COLOR.
SO YOU CAN BRING
A DATE HERE NOW.
WELL, YEAH.
THEY EVEN POURED IN A CEMENT
FLOOR IN THE BACK ROOM.
INDOOR PLUMBING?!
PLATING THE FOOD
FOR THE PEOPLE.
WHAT MADE YOU COME HERE?
JAMES BEARD AWARD
OVER THERE.
NICE. THE FAMOUS
JAMES BEARD AWARD
JUST HANGING HERE
UP NEXT TO THE GODZILLA.
IT'S NOT THE PRETTIEST PLACE
YOU'RE EVER GONNA EAT AT,
BUT IT'S GOOD FOOD
EVERY TIME.
SOMEBODY TAKE THIS. I THINK
HE ORDERED WHITE TOAST.
I NEEDED
THAT JOSE YESTERDAY!
I GET ONE THING--
THE SMOKY JOSE...
A SMOKY JOSE AGAIN.
HASH BROWNS, POACHED EGG,
SAUCE ON THAT,
AND THEN
THE SMOKY CHEDDAR CHEESE.
BEST BREAKFAST IN TOWN.
SPRING SPECIAL.
PEOPLE ACTUALLY LINE UP
AND THEY'LL WAIT FOR AN HOUR.
AN HOUR!
THAT'S NOT TOO BAD, THOUGH.
PEOPLE BEHIND YOU KIND OF
KICKING YOU AND PRODDING YOU
TO GET OUT OF YOUR WAY.
LIKE, "STOP TALKING."
SHUT UP AND EAT
SO I CAN SIT DOWN.
EAT YOUR LOAD
AND HIT THE ROAD!
WHEN YOU'RE HUNGRY, THE LAST
THING I WANT TO DO IS WAIT.
THIS IS THE NUMBER ONE PLACE
TO GO.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S A CHARMING, DUMPY PLACE.
OH, HO! WAIT A MINUTE.
DUMPY?!
GOT A PICK-UP.
YOU TOLD US LAST TIME...
WE'RE SORT OF A DUMP
ASPIRING TO BE A DIVE.
EVERYBODY WANTS TO KNOW. THEY'RE
ON THE EDGE OF THEIR SEAT.
WE'VE BEEN WORKING HARD.
JUST BETWEEN YOU AND ME,
WOULD YOU CALL THIS PLACE
A DUMP OR A DIVE?
IT'S A DIVE.
IT'S A DIVE?
ONE VOTE FOR DIVE.
DUMP OR DIVE?
DEFINITELY A DIVE.
DIVE.
THAT'S TWO.
DUMP OR IS IT NOW A DIVE?
DIVE EXCEPTIONNEL.
THAT'S THREE.
WE ARE A DIVE!
OFFICIALLY A DIVE AT AL'S.
AFTER 60 YEARS,
THEY'VE GRADUATED. TAKE IT EASY.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TIME TO ACTIVATE.
I HAVE THE CODE.
CLICK.
ACTIVATE THE BANANA.
WHEW!
(laughs)