HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ONE HUNGARIAN.
THE FOOD IS THE REAL DEAL.
GONE GLOBAL.
AUTHENTIC SICILIAN-ITALIAN.
THIS IS JUST OUTRAGEOUS.
IN FALLS CHURCH, VIRGINIA...
THIS IS THE PLACE
YOU NEED TO COME TO,
BECAUSE IT'S AUTHENTIC.
THE LOCAL FAVORITE
SERVED UP FRIED...
THERE'S LOVE IN THAT.
BAKED...
MMM, THAT'S WONDERFUL.
AND STUFFED...
(man) AREPA.
SOUTH AMERICAN CLASSICS.
MMM. IT'S AWESOME, DUDE.
IN NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE...
EVERYTHING HERE
IS TOTALLY FRESH.
THE ITALIAN JOINT...
STUFFED SHELLS ARE READY.
ROLLIN' IT OUT...
(Guy) I'VE NEVER SEEN IT
DONE LIKE THIS.
OLD-SCHOOL.
CONSISTENTLY THIN
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
AND TO TOP IT OFF...
CANTALOUPE ITALIAN ICE.
NOW WE TAKE IT, POP IT
INTO THE GELATO MACHINE
TO DO THE SUPER FREEZE.
RIGHT.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
AND IN
SHERMAN OAKS, CALIFORNIA...
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SAUERKRAUT
COMING UP.
THE GERMAN SAUSAGE HOUSE...
THEY'VE GOT THE BEST BRATS
IN L.A.
THAT'S A TRIPLE "D"...
IT'S JUST PLAIN GOOD.
VIEWER'S CHOICE.
BRATS BROTHERS ROCKS!
THAT'S ALL COMIN' UP
RIGHT HERE
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
(chuckles)
FUNKY, FUNKY,
FUNKY, FUNKY.
WE SAY IT ON TRIPLE "D"
ALL THE TIME.
IF IT'S FUNKY,
OF COURSE WE'LL FIND IT.
I MEAN, I THINK IF YOU LOOK UP
THE WORD "FUNKY"
IN THE DICTIONARY IN FLAVORTOWN,
IT'S GONNA BE A PICTURE
OF THIS JOINT.
HERE WE ARE IN
FALLS CHURCH, VIRGINIA,
TO VISIT A PLACE THAT'S MAKIN'
LATIN AMERICAN FOOD.
BUT THEY'RE SPECIALIZING
IN SOME REALLY DYNAMITE
VENEZUELAN AND BOLIVIAN DISHES.
NOW THAT'S NOT THE PART
THAT MAKES IT FUNKY.
THE FUNKY PART IS THEY'RE
CONNECTED TO A MOTEL.
THIS IS LA CARAQUEÑA, DONDE
LA COMIDA ES MUY SABROSO.
THAT MEANS
THE FOOD'S REALLY GOOD.
SALTEÑAS ARE DONE.
(woman) SO AUTHENTIC,
SO GOOD,
EVEN IF IT'S
IN A MOTEL.
(speaking Spanish)
GRACIAS.
(woman) IF YOU'VE NEVER HAD
SOUTH AMERICAN FOOD,
THIS IS THE PLACE
YOU NEED TO COME TO,
BECAUSE IT'S PERFECT.
GREAT FOOD, AMAZING HOST.
THAT'D BE CHEF AND OWNER
RAUL CLAROS...
ALL RIGHT, ARE YOU READY?
SERVIN' UP HIS MOM'S
SOUTH AMERICAN FAVORITES.
FRIED YUCCA
AND SOME SALSA PICANTE.
MMM, THERE'S LOVE IN THAT.
OF COURSE.
THAT'S THE KEY.
ORDER UP.
(bell rings)
WHEN I MOVED BACK
TO VENEZUELA,
I JOINED
THE CULINARY SCHOOL...
THAT'S GOOD.
SO I JUST HAD TO GO
BACK TO MY ROOTS.
LIKE THIS
VENEZUELAN CLASSIC,
AN AREPA.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A LATINO ENGLISH MUFFIN.
UH-HUH.
(man) RAUL STUFFS THEM
SO BIG THAT THEY
LOOK LIKE CLAMSHELLS
THAT ARE OVERFLOWING.
WITH BEEF...
KIND OF MESSY, BUT GOOD.
VEGGIES...
WHITE CHEESE AND BLACK BEANS.
AND CHICKEN.
REALLY CLASSIC CHICKEN
SALAD IN VENEZUELA.
ALL RIGHT, WE MAKE SOME
HOMEMADE MAYONNAISE.
EGG YOLKS, PEPPER, AND SALT,
SUGAR AND THEN MIX IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BUTTER TO THE OIL.
BUTTER FOR THE FLAVOR,
AND SLOWLY INCORPORATE IT.
WE ADD SOME MUSTARD.
LEMON JUICE.
YEAH.
VINEGAR, JUST
A LITTLE TOUCH.
WE GET TO
THE RIGHT CONSISTENCY.
PUT IT IN
THE REFRIGERATOR.
YEP.
OKAY, CHICKEN'S BEEN
SALTED AND PEPPERED
AND ROASTED, AND NOW WE'RE
GONNA MAKE THE CHICKEN SALAD.
CHOP SOME CHICKEN.
ADD THIS TO THE BOWL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME MAYONNAISE.
LOOKS LIKE IT'S
RIGHT OUT OF A JAR, HUH?
GONNA ADD SOME AVOCADOS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME
MUSTARD, SALT, AND PEPPER.
AND THEN SALSA INGLESA.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED HOW MANY
TIMES YOU'LL SEE SALSA INGLESA,
THE WORCESTERSHIRE
SAUCE, THERE,
AND HOW MANY TIMES
IT'S USED.
THIS IS THE BEST PART.
SQUISHIN' THE CHICKEN.
SQUISHIN' THE AVOCADO
INTO THE CHICKEN.
MORE LIKE CHICKEN GUACAMOLE,
'CAUSE THAT'S THE WAY
IT WAS DONE IN OLD-SCHOOL
VENEZUELA.
YEAH.
OH, I LOVE AVOCADO
AND POULTRY.
MAKIN' THAT MAYONNAISE
YOURSELF--PRIMO, MAN.
REALLY NICE, AND THIS CHICKEN
SALAD'S GOING INTO WHAT?
INTO THE AREPA.
ADD SOME WATER.
THIS IS CORNMEAL FLOUR.
I'M GONNA INCORPORATE
IT SLOWLY.
IT ABSORBS ALL
THE WATER?
THAT'S IT.
SO IT'S LIKE
TAMALE DOUGH OR TORTILLAS.
GOTTA HAVE THE RIGHT
MOISTURE IN THIS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON THE GRILL.
THIS IS INTERESTING.
BUTTER? NOTHING? JUST--
JUST LIKE THAT.
TAKE IT. PUT IT IN A TOWEL.
OPEN IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
SOME BUTTER,
THEN CHICKEN SALAD.
WHOA!
JUST LIKE THAT, BROTHER.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE.
MMM, IT'S AWESOME, DUDE.
THE AREPA BY ITSELF
HAS JUST REALLY GOT
NICE CRUNCH
AND NICE TEXTURE.
THEN ONCE YOU GET
THROUGH THAT,
YOU GET THIS CREAMY
CHICKEN SALAD--
REALLY VELVETY AND SMOOTH.
YOU REALLY TASTE THE CHICKEN.
JUST SIMPLE FLAVORS DONE RIGHT.
NOT OVERSEASONED.
DELICIOUS. IF YOU LIKE
CHICKEN SALAD SANDWICHES,
CATCH THE FIRST BUS
COMIN' HERE.
REALLY GOOD.
ENJOY IT. AREPA.
IT'S INCREDIBLY CREAMY.
ALL THE FLAVORS COME THROUGH.
IT'S JUST LOVELY.
(Raul) ORDER UP.
FIRST TIME YOU CAME IN,
WHAT'D YOU THINK?
I WAS--
KNOCKED MY SOCKS OFF.
LIKE, WOW?
YEAH.
MMM, GOOD STUFF.
WE FOUND A PLACE WE WERE
GONNA BE REGULARS AT.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD HERE
IS REALLY GOOD.
TWO MORE MEALS.
ESPECIALLY GIVEN THE CALIBER
OF FOOD THAT HE PUTS OUT.
THE VENEZUELAN CLASSICS
AND FOOD FROM ALL OVER
THE REST OF SOUTH AMERICA,
LIKE BARROS,
CHILEAN SANDWICHES,
BOLIVIAN PEANUT SOUP...
THE SOPA de MANí
IS FANTASTIC.
AND SOMETHING CALLED
A SALTEÑA
BORN IN ARGENTINA.
(man) A POCKETFUL OF MULTITUDES
OF FLAVORS.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
LET THE GREATNESS BEGIN.
THE FIRST THING WE'LL DO,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME HOMEMADE BEEF STOCK.
THEN WE ADD HOMEMADE
CHICKEN STOCK.
WE ADD SOME CUMIN
AND OREGANO.
GROUND-UP ANNATTO?
YES.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER.
BLACK PEPPER
AND POWDERED GARLIC.
CAJUN SEASONING?
YES, SIR.
SALT...
(speaking Spanish)
WHAT IS THAT?
MONOSODIUM GLUTAMATE?
THAT'S IT.
WELL, I'M DOIN'
A BIG OLD FINGER OF THAT.
NOW WE ADD SOME ONIONS.
EVERYTHING COOKS
INSIDE THE LIQUID?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HMM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD A MIXTURE
OF CARROTS AND JALAPEÑOS.
SUGAR, GROUND BEEF.
BIG CHILI GRIND ON THAT.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME POTATOES.
PEAS. CURLY LEAF PARSLEY.
AND HOW LONG'S THIS
GONNA SIMMER?
ABOUT, LIKE,
15 MINUTES.
THAT'S IT?
WE DON'T WANT TO
OVERCOOK THE POTATOES.
GELATIN.
THIS IS GONNA COAGULATE
EVERYTHING UP
SO IT STAYS TOGETHER.
THAT'S IT.
PUT IT IN THE ICE BATH.
IT COOLS DOWN QUICKLY.
THROW IT IN THE ICEBOX.
LET IT TIGHTEN UP.
WHAT DO WE GOTTA DO
NOW, BOSS?
FIRST WE MELT
THE SHORTENING.
AND THIS IS ALL GOING
TO MAKE A DOUGH?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE GONNA ADD
ANNATTO SEEDS.
ANNATTO SEEDS CREATE
THIS REALLY DEEP-RED COLOR.
AND STEEP THEM
TEN MINUTES.
STRAIN IT SO THE SEEDS
AREN'T IN THERE,
'CAUSE THEY'RE HARD.
LET IT COOL.
BEFORE WE START
MAKIN' THE DOUGH.
SO LET'S MAKE THE, UH,
SALTEÑA DOUGH.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THAT'S THE ANNATTO SEED
THAT STEEPED IN THE SHORTENING.
YOU'RE JUST LETTIN' THAT FAT
GET INCORPORATED
INTO THE FLOUR.
LOOK AT THAT BEAUTIFUL COLOR
THAT'S GOIN' ON IN THERE.
GONNA HIT A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER,
GET IT TO THE LEVEL
HE LOOKS FOR.
OKAY, SO THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT. WARM.
PUSH IT DOWN.
WHAT WE DO...
SO WE'RE GONNA DO
2 1/2 OUNCES.
MAGICAL RAUL WILL
NOW PERFORM
THE 2 1/2-OUNCE
DOUGH PULL.
CLOSE.
THAT'S GOOD.
WORK IT A LITTLE BIT.
SO YOU'RE ROLLING IT
ON YOUR PALMS?
JUST LIKE PIZZA DOUGH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
PUT 'EM IN THE BAG,
LET THE GLUTENS MELLOW OUT.
POP 'EM IN THE COOLER.
THEY'LL BE READY
FOR TOMORROW.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
OLIVE OIL, CHICKEN BREASTS,
SALT AND PEPPER AND BAKE IT
FOR 20 MINUTES.
THE CHICKEN'S READY
TO GO.
WE GOT OUR MIXTURE
COOLED DOWN.
GET THE DOUGH
WE ALREADY MADE.
IT'S READY TO GO?
YES, SIR.
GET THE LITTLE BALL.
FLATTEN IT A LITTLE BIT.
WORK IT LIKE THIS.
SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN, MAN.
SOME GUISO.
VENEZUELAN POT PIE.
A LITTLE CHICKEN.
SOME BOILED EGG.
EASY ON THE EGG, AND A LITTLE
OLIVE ON TOP, MAN.
THEN WE JUST CLOSE IT.
AND MAKE SURE
IT SEALS GOOD.
THAT'S A LOT
OF EXTRA EFFORT, MAN.
NICE. AND NOW YOU BAKE IT?
450 FOR HOW LONG?
FOR ABOUT 12 MINUTES.
12 MINUTES.
WOW. SERVE ME UP,
BROTHER.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
JUST RUN OUT OF THAT.
MMM. DYNAMITE, MAN.
THE TEXTURE OF THE DOUGH
IS PHENOMENAL.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
A LOT OF JUICE.
IT'S NOT DRY
BY ANY MEANS.
AND YOU SAY PEOPLE EAT THIS
WITH HOT SAUCE?
YEAH.
AND WHAT'S IN THIS?
JALAPEÑOS, TOMATO,
CILANTRO, ONION,
SALT, AND SOME OLIVE OIL.
GREEN HOT SAUCE.
MMM. OH-HO.
NOT A REAL SPICY SALSA.
THAT HAS GOT IT ALL--
SWEET, SALTY, SPICY.
YOU'VE GOTTA DO IT
WITH THE HOT SAUCE.
KILLER. I'LL EAT
20 OF THOSE.
SALTEÑAS ARE UP.
INCREDIBLE. MMM.
IT'S LIKE A LITTLE PUFF PASTRY
WITH JUICY GOODNESS INSIDE.
HE WORKS FOR HALLMARK.
THIS IS AMAZING.
GREAT FOOD, GREAT PRICES.
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
ORDER UP.
IT'S ALL ABOUT HAVING FUN,
ENJOYING WHAT YOU DO.
(woman) THIS PLACE
MAKES YOU HAPPY.
(Guy) IT MAY BE A SMALL,
LITTLE VENEZUELAN RESTAURANT
CONNECTED TO
A FUNKY LITTLE HOTEL,
BUT, DUDE,
YOU'RE ON YOUR GAME
PROFESSIONALLY BIG-TIME.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE
HEADIN' TO NASHVILLE...
RAGU IS READY.
THE HOMEMADE FETTUCCINI NOODLES,
IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
TO KEEP ON ROLLIN'.
IT'S SO THIN,
IT ONLY HAS ONE SIDE.
NOW I DON'T THINK
IT'S ANY BIG SECRET
THAT I LOVE ITALIAN FOOD.
I MEAN, WITH THE LAST NAME
FIERI, WHAT DO YOU EXPECT?
SO HERE I AM
SMACK-DAB IN THE CENTER
OF NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE,
JUST A FEW BLOCKS AWAY
FROM VANDERBILT UNIVERSITY,
TO VISIT A JOINT
THAT'S MAKIN' IT ALL.
I MEAN, THEY'RE MAKIN'
THE BREAD, THE ITALIAN ICE,
THE PASTA, YOU NAME IT.
THIS IS SAVARINO'S CUCINA.
STUFFED SHELLS ARE READY.
REAL ITALIAN.
MAKIN' THE MEATBALLS.
AUTHENTIC SICILIAN-ITALIAN.
THANKS TO SICILIAN-BORN OWNERS
CORRADO SAVARINO.
THE RAGU IS READY.
AND HIS WIFE MARIA.
MOZZARELLA.
(Corrado) IT WAS NINE YEARS
AGO WHEN WE MOVED HERE.
THREE AND A HALF YEARS AGO,
WE OPENED UP THIS PLACE.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO COOK?
MOSTLY MY WIFE.
AND SHE'S STILL
FILLIN' THE MENU
WITH THE FAVORITES
SHE GREW UP WITH.
(Maria) CHICKEN PARM.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
THE HOMEMADE SAUCE. I LOVE IT.
WHITE BREAD.
THE HOMEMADE BREAD
AND THE HOMEMADE PASTA.
FETTUCCINI WITH
THE VODKA SAUCE.
THE HOMEMADE FETTUCCINI
NOODLES--IT'S OUT OF THIS WORLD.
FETTUCCINI
WITH VODKA SAUCE.
(man) PASTA FRESH
EVERY DAY.
IT DOESN'T GET ANY
BETTER THAN THAT.
WANNA MAKE
FETTUCCINI?
YEAH.
THEN LET'S MAKE IT.
WE'RE GONNA USE
SEMOLINA FLOUR.
I START THE MACHINE FIRST,
THEN PUT THE EGGS.
HOW MANY EGGS DID YOU
JUST ADD IN THERE?
I PUT ABOUT 20.
WHO'S COUNTIN'?
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OLIVE OIL.
AND THEN WE JUST LET IT MIX
AT THE SECOND SPEED
FOR THREE, FOUR MINUTES.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA USE
A MACHINE TO ROLL THIS OUT?
NO, I USE A ROLLING PIN.
I-I AM LATE
FOR SOME IMPORTANT--
TAKE TWO SECONDS.
I WILL BE BACK.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
GOOD LUCK ON THAT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
KNEAD THE DOUGH
BEFORE IT RESTS.
I PUT A BOWL--
RIGHT.
JUST COVER IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA LET IT REST
FOR 20 MINUTES, THEN IT'S READY
TO BE STRETCHED OUT.
(whistles)
SO NOW YOU JUST
SLICE A LITTLE PIECE.
YOU DUST A LITTLE BIT
OF FLOUR.
AND I USE THE ROLLING PIN,
AND THIS IS WHERE ME AND MY
WIFE ARGUE ALL THE TIME
BECAUSE SHE USES
A BROOMSTICK.
MARIA?
COME HERE, MARIA.
CAN YOU SHOW ME HOW
TO DO THIS, PLEASE?
WHAT'S THE MATTER WITH
THE WAY I WAS DOIN' IT?
OH, SEE, WE SEE A WHOLE
DIFFERENT STYLE
RIGHT OFF THE BAT. I'VE NEVER
SEEN IT DONE LIKE THIS.
MY GRANDMOTHER USED
TO MAKE IT LIKE THAT.
IT'S OLD-FASHIONED.
YOU CAN KEEP GOIN'
ON YOURS.
I THOUGHT I WAS OFF THE HOOK.
YOU DON'T LIKE MY THING?
IT'S BIG NOODLE DAY HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
OH, CHECK THIS METHOD OUT.
SO YOU GET NICE UNIFORM--
CONSISTENTLY THIN
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
CAN I SEE
ONE OF YOURS?
I'M TRYIN' MY BEST.
FIND THAT THIN ONE.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
OOH.
MINE YOU CAN
SEE THROUGH.
YOU CAN SEE THROUGH?
HERS IS SO THIN,
IT ONLY HAS ONE SIDE.
I FEEL DEJECTED NOW.
WELL, THIS WAS AMAZING.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE WITH THIS?
VODKA SAUCE.
FETTUCCINI AND VODKA SAUCE.
I LIKE ALL THE PARTS
OF THAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
HEAT THIS UP A LITTLE BIT.
PUT IN SOME ONIONS. NOW
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME MARINARA.
AND WHAT'S IN THE MARINARA?
IT'S CRUSHED TOMATOES,
OREGANO,
A LITTLE BIT OF BASIL.
NOW WE'LL PUT THE VODKA.
PUTTING THAT VODKA--
IT DOESN'T BURN OFF ALL
THE ALCOHOL, BY THE WAY,
BECAUSE OF HOW MUCH LIQUID'S
ALREADY IN THERE.
THERE'S JUST
THIS UNIQUE FLAVOR
THAT GOES ALONG WITH
THE TOMATO SAUCE.
PRETTY CRAZY COMBO.
NOW WHILE THIS
IS DOIN' ITS THING,
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE PASTA IN.
FRESH PASTA
GOES REAL QUICK
ABOUT A MINUTE.
NOW WE'LL PUT THE CREAM.
JUST A TOUCH.
LOOK AT THAT.
PASTA COMES UP.
YOU GRAB IT.
I LIKE IT AL DENTE.
FRESH-MADE PASTA
WITH A NICE, LIGHT
VODKA SAUCE LIKE THIS--OH.
AND WE'RE READY.
TAKE THIS OFF
AND PUT THAT ON THE PLATE.
AND PECORINO ROMANO?
YOU BRING IN THE WHOLE WHEEL
AND BREAK IT DOWN
AND FRESH-GRATE IT?
GRATE IT EVERY MORNING.
OH, THAT'S IT.
THIS IS JUST EXCELLENT.
THERE IS A TEXTURAL
DIFFERENCE ON FRESH PASTA.
THE WAY IT SEIZES UP
GIVES THE NICE CHEW TO IT,
BUT IT'S SOFT.
THAT IS MY COMFORT FOOD 101,
AND THE PECORINO ROMANO--
IT MAKES ALL THE DIFFERENCE
IN THE WORLD.
NICE AND SHARP. MMM.
THIS IS JUST OUTRAGEOUS.
I COULD EAT
THIS ENTIRE PLATE.
WHAT? I THOUGHT WE
WENT TO COMMERCIAL.
YOU COOK THE PASTA.
IT JUST MELTS IN
YOUR MOUTH.
FETTUCCINI WITH VODKA SAUCE
IS READY.
THE SAUCE IS SO FLAVORFUL.
INCREDIBLE.
(Corrado)
PENNE RAGU.
EVERYTHING
IS GOOD HERE.
RICE BALL IS READY.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS TOTALLY FRESH.
YOU GOTTA MAKE
YOUR OWN STUFF.
GOTTA BE REAL.
THAT'S THE WHOLE
ATTITUDE HERE.
YEAH.
THAT'S HOW CORRADO'S BEEN DOIN'
THINGS SINCE HE STARTED
IN THE BAKING BIZ.
YOU TURNED 15 AND THEN
YOU STARTED BAKIN'?
RIGHT. NEVER STOPPED.
THIS DAY-TO-DAY
BREAD THAT HE MAKES--
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST
IN THE CITY.
SO GOOD, HE'S ALSO DOIN'
ABOUT 1,000 LOAVES A DAY
FOR LOCAL RESTAURANTS
AND HOTELS.
I CAN'T EVEN COUNT
THAT HIGH.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THE WRIST OVER HERE?
FORGET ABOUT IT.
IT'S POWERFUL.
THE BACK'S--
THE BACK'S NOT.
PENNE PELLEGRINO.
THE BREAD'S HERE
ARE HOMEMADE, DELICIOUS.
FROM THE HOMEMADE BREAD
THAT THEY MAKE EVERY DAY,
WHICH IS FANTASTIC.
LET'S MAKE SOME BREAD.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE WATER.
WARM WATER.
PUT SOME SALT.
YOU ACTUALLY MEASURE?
YEAH, 'CAUSE I'M USED TO WORKIN'
WITH A SCALE LIKE THIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
FRESH YEAST.
OH, YEAH.
AND HOW MUCH YEAST
DO WE GO WITH?
1 POUND.
WHOA, THAT'S
A LOT OF YEAST.
I START THE MACHINE. NOW WE'RE
GONNA SCALE THE FLOUR.
HOW MANY POUNDS ARE WE
GOIN' AFTER HERE?
11 POUNDS. THERE WE GO.
LET IT MIX NICE AND GOOD.
I JUST WAIT A FEW MINUTES.
LET IT MIX UP.
WE'LL BRING IT OUT.
LET ME KNOW
WHEN YOU'RE READY.
I'M READY
WHEN "YOUSE" ARE.
I'M READY.
WOW.
WE'LL SCALE 'EM TO A POUND.
I DIDN'T KNOW
IT WAS PLAY-DOH TIME.
SEE, WHERE I COME FROM,
WE JUST TRY TO GO AFTER
OUR OWN POUND
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
PERFECT.
HUH?
VERY GOOD.
OKAY.
NOW YOU ROLL 'EM.
IT'S LIKE PLAYIN' THE GUITAR.
THE FINGERS HAVE GOTTA
MOVE DIFFERENT TIME.
I'M GOOD WITH
THE RIGHT HAND.
I CAN'T GET MY LEFT
TO GO WITH MY RIGHT.
THIS GUY JUST KEEPS
WANDERING AWAY OVER HERE.
YOU'LL LEARN.
I'LL LEARN. I THINK MAYBE
MY 30 SECONDS OF DOING IT
TO YOUR 35 YEARS OF DOING IT
REALLY JUST IS KIND OF SHOWING
MY INEXPERIENCE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON A TRAY.
PUT IT IN THE PROOFER.
SO THESE ARE GONNA
GO DOWN FOR 20 MINUTES?
20 MINUTES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
ROLL 'EM AGAIN.
OKAY.
KNOCK 'EM DOWN AND THEN
ROLL 'EM UP AGAIN.
RIGHT, AND THEN WE'LL WAIT
ANOTHER 20 MINUTES,
AND THEN I'M GONNA
SHAPE 'EM.
OKAY, LET'S ROLL
ONE OF THESE OUT.
THIS IS THE WAY WE DO IT.
SMACK--THERE YOU GO.
SMACK IT LIKE THIS,
AND THEN YOU FOLD.
FOLD. BRING IT OVER.
JUST LET IT REST A LITTLE.
I AM GOOD.
IT'S NOT LIKE THIS.
WELL, I DIDN'T SEE YOU.
YOU STARTED SWINGIN'
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT--
SEE, THE SKIN HAS TO
GO UNDERNEATH.
PUT THE SKIN DOWN?
YEAH. AND WE GOTTA STRETCH
IT TO 24 INCHES NOW.
NOW WE'RE GOIN' TO 24.
STRETCH IT A LITTLE BIT
AT A TIME.
SEE, BUT THE ENDS,
TRY TO MAKE THEM INTO A POINT.
OKAY, SO WE LOOKIN' GOOD?
LIKE THAT?
YEAH.
NOW PUT 'EM ON THE TRAY.
NOW WE'LL LET IT RISE.
IN THE PROOFER
ANOTHER 20 MINUTES.
LOOKIN' NICE, HUH?
THIS IS PERFECT.
THESE MUST HAVE BEEN
THE ONES I DID.
HERE'S THE WAY WE JUST
SCORE THEM DOWN THE MIDDLE
NOW INTO THE OVEN?
THAT'S IT.
WHAT TEMPERATURE?
425.
425. SO WE'RE GOIN'
HOT AND FAST.
IT SHOULD TAKE ABOUT
9 TO 11 MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA CUT THIS,
AND WE'LL MAKE THE HEEL.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
AND THAT'S JUST THE START
OF MORE THAN A DOZEN SIGNATURE
SAVARINO'S SANDWICHES...
THAT'S HOW YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO DO A SANDWICH.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
SO WE JUST FINISHED MAKIN'
THE ITALIAN BREAD...
PERFECT.
THESE MUST HAVE BEEN
THE ONES I DID.
AT SAVARINO'S CUCINA
IN NASHVILLE.
READY.
AND NOW CORRADO SAVARINO
AND HIS WIFE MARIA...
NOW I MAKE THE FRANK.
ARE LOADIN' IT UP.
FRANK'S READY.
THE SANDWICHES ARE
WHAT SETS THE PLACE APART.
MORE THAN A DOZEN OF THEM...
YOU MAKE THE MEATBALL,
RIGHT?
SOME EVEN NAMED
FOR THEIR CUSTOMERS.
THE JOE IS COMIN' OUT.
JOE PAGETTA.
FRANK DILEO.
AND THE NICK.
(man) NICK PELLEGRINO.
IT'S MY SANDWICH.
EVERY TIME I COME IN HERE,
I CAN EAT IT
AND BE FULL OF MYSELF.
AND THE FRED MILLINI.
MY SANDWICH, THE FRED MILLINI,
IT'S A WORK OF ART.
IT'S A VERY ELITE GROUP TO
GET A SANDWICH ON THE BOARD.
THE ED PONTIERI.
I LOVE THE ED PONTIERI.
OH, THAT'S YOUR
BEST FRIEND.
YEAH, AND LET ME SHOW YOU
HOW WE MAKE HIS SANDWICH.
RIGHT? WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME RED CHILI.
PICKLED?
YEAH.
AND ARE THEY SPICY?
IT'S NOT THAT BAD.
OH, THEN YOU TRY ONE.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, CHOP
THE PEPPERS.
TWO SECONDS JUST
SLICES IT UP.
I KNOW I'VE SEEN THESE
BEFORE. THEY'RE CRAZY.
WE WANT TO PUT THE ARTICHOKES,
A LITTLE BIT OF EGGPLANT.
OH, YOU ROASTED
THE EGGPLANT OFF?
YEAH. A LITTLE BIT
OF ITALIAN SEASONING.
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
BUT YOU DON'T WANT
TO BREAK IT UP TOO MUCH.
NO. THERE WE GO.
WE'RE DONE WITH THIS.
NEXT WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME SANDWICHES.
LET'S GO.
WE'RE GONNA CUT THIS
INTO THREE.
ABOUT 8 INCHES APART.
THE HEEL IS THE BEST PART.
THAT'S WHAT I THINK.
SO WE'LL MAKE THE HEEL.
LOOK AT THAT.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF BOMBA.
SPREAD IT ON BOTH SIDES.
NOW WE'LL PUT
SOME MORTADELLA.
I LOVE MORTADELLA.
PUT SOME SOPRESSATA.
NOW DO YOU GET THIS
FROM HERE IN TOWN?
I GET THIS SHIPPED
OUT OF NEW YORK.
DO YOU REALLY?
YEAH.
CAPICOLA? MY MOUTH
IS STARTING TO RUN ALREADY.
NEXT IS THE PROVOLONE,
TOMATOES.
JUST DOIN' THIS RIGHT.
BALSAMIC VINEGAR
GOIN' ON.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
OVER THERE.
A LITTLE ITALIAN SEASONING.
ALL RIGHT. MANGI.
LOOK AT THAT.
AT HOME RIGHT NOW,
YOU'RE JUST JONSIN'.
SOMEONE'S RUNNIN'
DOWN THE STAIRS
TO GO MAKE A SANDWICH
RIGHT NOW.
MMM, OH, IS THAT GOOD?
AND THIS BREAD IS FANTASTIC.
AND RIGHT AFTER YOU GET
THROUGH THE BREAD,
YOU GET THE SPICE, THE BOMBA,
THEN IT COOLS DOWN.
THE LETTUCE, TOMATO, AND THEN
YOU GET THE SPICE AGAIN.
I MEAN, I'M SWEET
AND I'M SPICY.
I'M HOT. I'M SALTY.
I'M CHEWY.
THAT'S HOW YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO DO A SANDWICH.
THANK YOU.
ED PONTIERI'S READY.
(man) THE SWEETNESS
AND THIS FIRE--
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
THE ED PONTIERI.
CLASSIC ITALIAN SANDWICH.
EVERYTHING--
UNBELIEVABLE.
JOE PAGETTA'S READY.
YOU MAKE THE BREAD.
YOU MAKE THE SAUCE.
AND HE'S NOT DONE YET.
ZUPPA INGLESE GELATO
IS READY!
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST
DESSERTS IN TOWN.
THE CANNOLI, CHEESECAKE...
HOW WAS THAT ONE?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT
IT IS, BUT IT IS GOOD.
YOU MAKE ALL THESE PASTRIES.
YOU NAME IT, YOU MAKE IT.
YEAH. THAT'S RIGHT.
EVEN THE FROZEN STUFF...
CANTALOUPE ITALIAN ICE.
FROM A RECIPE HE PICKED UP
BACK IN NEW YORK.
MMM.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
ACTUAL REAL FRUIT IN THERE.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S GOTTA BE A GOOD
CANTALOUPE.
SO YOU MAKE THIS
WHEN IT'S IN SEASON.
YEAH. TAKE OUT
THE SEEDS.
NO SPOON NECESSARY HERE.
WANNA HEAR
SOMETHING FUNNY?
YEAH, I'M ALWAYS LOOKIN'
FOR SOMETHING FUNNY.
I WOULD NOT EAT
A CANTALOUPE IF YOU PAY ME.
BUT WHEN I MAKE IT INTO THE ICE,
I CAN MAKE IT ALL GONE.
REALLY?
I DON'T KNOW WHY. I SWEAR
TO GOD. SO HERE'S WHAT WE DO.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PURéE IT.
SO WE POP THAT ON.
YOU DON'T WANT CHUNKS,
DO YOU?
NO.
IT'S GOTTA BE
NICE AND SMOOTH.
THAT'S PERFECT.
OKAY, IT'S READY.
SO WE TAKE THIS.
WE MIX IT UP.
LET ME PUT
SOME SUGAR IN HERE.
THE SUPERFINE SUGAR,
BECAUSE IF YOU USE REGULAR
SUGAR, THE GRANULES WILL BE
TOO BIG AND WON'T BREAK DOWN
UNLESS YOU WERE TO HEAT THEM UP.
WE'RE NOT HEATING THIS UP.
YEAH. NOW WE'RE
GONNA PUT MILK.
I WHISK THIS. NOW IF THIS
IS TOO LIGHT COLOR,
YOU MIGHT HAVE TO PUT FOOD COLOR
SO IT'S MORE PINK. SEE?
SO NOW IT'S PINK.
WHEN IT COMES OUT
OF THE MACHINE,
YOU'LL SEE THE--
THE CANTALOUPE.
IT'S GONNA BE ORANGE?
IT BETTER BE,
'CAUSE THAT LOOKS LIKE
PEPTO-BISMOL TO ME RIGHT NOW.
SO NOW WE TAKE IT, POP IT
IN THE GELATO MACHINE.
TO DO THE SUPER FREEZE.
YOU TICKLISH?
AM I TICKLISH?
NO.
LIAR.
NOW YOU COME BACK
IN NINE MINUTES.
IT'S GOTTA FREEZE UP.
AND HERE IT COMES.
SHOULD WE TASTE IT?
YEAH.
THAT'S CRAZY. IT'S LIGHT.
IT'S GOT TONS OF FLAVOR.
EVERY TIME YOU MAKE IT,
IT'S ALL NATURAL LIKE THIS?
YEAH.
NO MIXES. NO BLENDS.
NO.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
GREAT JOB.
CANTALOUPE ITALIAN ICE.
OH, FANTASTIC.
CANTALOUPE ITALIAN
ICE.
YOU TASTE THE CANTALOUPE.
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE ABOUT IT.
AND YOU CAN TELL
THAT IT'S REAL FRUIT.
CORRADO JR.'s READY.
(woman) IT'S FRESH INGREDIENTS
THAT MAKES EVERY NOTE
DIFFERENT AND BETTER.
FETTUCCINI WITH VODKA SAUCE.
IF YOU'RE LOOKIN' FOR GOOD FOOD,
THIS IS WHERE YOU COME.
(Corrado) STUFFED SHELL
IS READY.
WE LOVE IT HERE.
RED PEPPER.
IT'S THE BEST.
ED PONTIERI'S READY.
YOU MAKE YOUR BREAD.
YOU DO THE WHOLE THING.
I GOTTA TELL YOU, MAN,
I'VE BEEN TO SOME GREAT JOINTS.
(clicks tongue) THIS IS
UP THERE WITH THEM.
THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS FOR HAVIN' US.
THANK YOU.
NEXT UP...
HERE YOU GO.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CALIFORNIA...
ONE HUNGARIAN.
WHERE IT'S YOUR TURN...
THEY GOT THE BEST BRATS
IN L.A.
TO SHOW ME THE REAL DEAL.
THIS IS THE BEST, ABSOLUTELY.
YOU GOTTA KNOW I'M ALL ABOUT
THE TOTALLY UNEXPECTED,
LIKE AUTHENTIC CHINESE
IN ALASKA,
REAL-DEAL CUBAN IN MINNESOTA,
AND GET THIS--
HANDMADE GERMAN SAUSAGE RIGHT
OUTSIDE OF LOS ANGELES,
IN SHERMAN OAKS, CALIFORNIA.
A BUNCH OF FOLKS WROTE IN
TO TELL ME ABOUT THAT ONE,
AND NOW, THEY'RE GONNA SHOW
ME THAT ONE--BRATS BROTHERS.
BRATS BROTHERS ROCKS!
MY NAME IS WOLF McCARRON,
AND I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THEY GOT THE BEST BRATS
IN L.A.
MY NAME'S KIM HENDERSON,
AND YOU'VE GOTTA CHECK OUT
BRATS BROTHERS,
BECAUSE THEIR BRATS
ARE THE BEST.
SEEMS LIKE IT'S UNANIMOUS.
ONE HOT ITALIAN.
OWNER ROLAND RADLER
IS GETTIN' IT RIGHT.
POLISH WITH FROZEN POTATOES
AND SAUERKRAUT.
THEY'RE JUST AMAZING.
ONE HUNGARIAN.
VERY AUTHENTIC.
I'M FROM MUNICH, GERMANY.
I MADE AT LEAST SIX
TRIPS TO GERMANY
TO PERFECT THE BRATWURST.
AND THEN HE STARTED PLAYIN'...
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SAUERKRAUT
COMING UP.
AND ENDED UP WITH
23 DIFFERENT KINDS.
WE WANTED TO HAVE
A REALLY GOOD SAUSAGE PLACE.
HE HAS SO MANY
DIFFERENT VARIETIES.
(Roland) ONE POLISH.
YOU GUYS TOLD ME HE'S
GOT THE BASICS COVERED.
I HAVE THE--THE GERMAN ONE.
IT'S LIKE AT HOME. MMM.
I USUALLY GET
THE WEISSWURST...
(Roland) THIS
IS A SWISS.
WHICH IS MADE WITH VEAL.
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
I WAS BORN IN POLAND, SO THAT'S
WHY I HAVE A POLISH BRAT.
(Roland) WHICH IS
A SMOKED PORK BRAT.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
TASTES LIKE MY GRANDMA'S.
ONE BLACKFOREST,
POTATO SALAD.
MADE WITH BLACKFOREST HAM
AND BACON.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S REALLY GREAT. IT'S ONE
THAT'S IN MY ROTATION.
ALL-AMERICAN
WITH RAW ONIONS.
YOU ALSO TOLD ME HE'S GOIN'
WAY BEYOND THE BASICS.
ALL RIGHT, I HAVE A FRENCH
AND AN ELK.
AND WE'VE GOT
ONE KANGAROO.
WHICH WAS FANTASTIC.
WE HAVE WILD BOAR,
DUCK, OSTRICH.
I NEED ONE KANGAROO,
ONE ELK.
MY FAVORITE WOULD
HAVE TO BE THE ELK.
(man) IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S LIKE I'M INFUSED WITH
THE SPIRIT OF THE WILD.
(Kim) TODAY I'VE GOT
THE WILD WEST,
WHICH IS
THE BUFFALO-SMOKED BRAT.
HERE YOU GO.
(woman) THEY ALL HAVE
REALLY DISTINCTIVE FLAVORS.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
AND ACCORDING TO YOU,
SO ARE THE SIDES.
I NORMALLY GO
WITH THE TATER TOTS.
BAVARIAN TATER TOTS
ARE READY.
A LITTLE BALL
OF POTATO FUN.
THEY'RE AWESOME.
I'VE NEVER HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THEM.
AND A BUNCH OF YOU
HAVE A TASTE
FOR ROLAND'S SOUTH
BAVARIAN-STYLE SPAETZLE.
YOU'VE GOTTA CHECK OUT
THE SPAETZLE.
IT'S LIKE A GERMAN
MAC AND CHEESE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TOTALLY AUTHENTIC.
(Roland) WE'RE MAKING
THE PASTA HERE.
THEN WE'RE USING
IMPORTED SWISS CHEESE.
IT TASTES REALLY FRESH.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
(Roland) BLACKFOREST,
POTATO SALAD AND SPAETZLE.
IT'S ALL JUST PLAIN GOOD.
(Wolf) I HAVEN'T
BEEN TO GERMANY,
BUT, I MEAN, I KNOW IT'S GOOD.
I KNOW GOOD FOOD.
(Roland) ONE SAMPLE PLATE.
THE FOOD IS THE REAL DEAL.
THIS IS THE BEST, ABSOLUTELY.
I'M GONNA GET TO EATING.
(laughs)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I THINK WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO TELL WHICH ONE'S MINE.
(humming
"The Streets of Cairo")
SORRY.
THEY'LL TASTE THE SAME.