HEY, EVERYBODY,
I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
WINGS...
OOH, HOT.
DOGS...
MMM.
AND CLAWS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
IN KANSAS CITY, MISSOURI...
HERE WE GO, FOLKS.
THE MUSIC JOINT...
THE FOOD HAS ALWAYS
BEEN WONDERFUL.
DOIN' BAR FOOD CLASSICS...
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH,
SWEET POTATO FRIES.
AND DROPPIN' DOGS...
OH, THAT IS JUST...
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
OKLAHOMA DOG.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
IN WASHINGTON, D.C...
FRIED CHICKEN.
THE LOCAL JOINT...
GRAVY ON THE MEAT LOAF.
SERVIN' UP SOUL FOOD
FAVORITES...
THE BEEF RUB'S
JUST PHENOMENAL.
AND WINGS SAUCED FROM SCRATCH.
MY MOUTH IS ALREADY
STARTIN' TO WATER.
AND IN SALEM, MASSACHUSETTS...
JUST LOVE IT HERE.
THE LOBSTER SHACK...
LOBSTER ROLL.
CRANKIN' OUT WHAT ELSE?
SMOKED PORK...
DELICIOUS. GREAT RUB.
AND...
TASTES LIKE THE OCEAN.
A LOBSTER MARTINI.
I'M A LITTLE WARY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO HERE I AM IN KANSAS CITY
IN THE CROSSROADS ARTS DISTRICT.
NOW DOES THAT SOUND FAMILIAR?
WELL, IT SHOULD, BECAUSE I'M
LIKE A BLOCK AND A HALF AWAY
FROM ONE OF OUR FAVORITE
TRIPLE "D" CHARACTERS STRETCH,
YOU KNOW, AND HIS JOINT
GRINDERS.
SO WHAT IS IT
ABOUT THIS NEIGHBORHOOD?
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN'
MUSIC VENUES WITH HOMEMADE FOOD,
LIKE THIS JOINT--
THE BRICK.
CAME FOR THE MUSIC,
STAYED FOR THE FOOD.
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH,
SWEET POTATO FRIES.
BEST MEAT LOAF EVER.
THE APPLE BUTTER
AND BRIE FOR YOU.
BRIE AND APPLE BUTTER--
DELICIOUS ON RYE BREAD.
I DON'T EVEN CONSIDER IT
BAR FOOD.
SHE SORT OF ELEVATES BAR FOOD
TO A NEW LEVEL.
"SHE" IS FORMER BARTENDER
SHERI PARR.
I COOK. I CLEAN.
I BOOK THE BANDS.
WELCOME TO THE BRICK.
SOUNDS LIKE
YOU OWN THE JOINT.
I OWN THE JOINT.
OH, YOU OWN THE JOINT.
SINCE '99...
HERE WE GO, FOLKS.
WHEN SHE STARTED CRANKIN' OUT
BAR FOOD...
MEAT LOAF'S COMIN' UP.
HER WAY.
IT'S BETTER THAN BAR FOOD.
CRUNCHY THAI CHICKEN SALAD--
THAT IS SUPER.
PORK TENDERLOIN--
JUST TO DIE FOR.
OKLAHOMA AND TOTS.
OKLAHOMA DOGS.
A DEEP-FRIED HOT DOG.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
WHAT ARE WE
MAKIN' FIRST?
THE OKLAHOMA DOG.
WE'RE MAKIN' THE BATTER.
IT'S GOT FLOUR, SUGAR,
BAKING POWDER,
A LITTLE SALT,
AND ONE EGG.
MIX THAT TOGETHER.
WITH SOME BEER.
WANT ME TO DRIZZLE?
PLEASE.
SO WHAT DO--
OH, IN THERE.
THAT'S GOOD.
REALLY? THAT'S A PRETTY
TIGHT BATTER, HUH?
YEAH.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
DO WITH THIS?
WE HAVE 1/4-POUND,
ALL-BEEF HOT DOGS.
WRAP THE BACON
AROUND THEM.
HOW MANY PIECES
OF BACON?
TWO. WE'RE GOING
TO TOOTHPICK IT
AND THEN ROLL IT
IN THE BEER BATTER.
THAT'S NOT GOOD
FOR THE GUIDO.
ALL RIGHT.
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA DEEP-FRY IT?
YES.
OH, THAT IS JUST--
TOAST A SOURDOUGH BUN, AND THEN
I GET MY TOOTHPICKS OUT.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, OKLAHOMA DOG.
HOLY SCHNIKE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
YEAH, IT IS.
DOES ANYTHING ELSE
GO ON THIS?
YEAH, WE CAN PUT SOME MUSTARD
AND SOME ONIONS ON IT.
THAT'S HOW WE SERVE IT.
I GOTTA JUST TAKE
A LOOK AT IT.
SO THERE YOU ARE. YOU'RE
WALKIN' DOWN THE STREET,
AND SOMEONE SAYS, "HEY, HOW
ABOUT 4,000 CALORIES IN A BUN?"
(laughs)
MMM. WOW. THAT'S COOL.
I'VE BEEN ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN
ANYBODY ADULTERATE A DOG
IN THIS FORM.
"SUPERMEGAJUICY" HOT DOG--
THAT'S ONE WORD--
WRAPPED IN "le BAY-CONE"--
THAT'S FRENCH, SO YOU KNOW
IT'S GOOD--
CRUNCHI-FIED IN BEER BATTER.
THAT'S FUNK-ALICIOUS.
EH, YOU BETTER TRY IT.
YOU--BAD PERSON.
(laughs)
I NEED ANOTHER
OKLAHOMA DOG.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
THE BACON, I THINK,
IS WHAT SETS IT OFF.
IT IS AWESOME,
DEFINITELY FILLING.
THIS IS REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
THAT'S A BRICK DISH.
WHICH MEANS HANDMADE...
CUBAN CHICKEN IN FOUR MINUTES.
AND CLASSIC, BUT DIFFERENT.
THE PUBBY WITH
SWEET POTATO FRIES.
THE MENU'S FULL OF THEM.
I NEED ANOTHER OKLAHOMA DOG
AND ANOTHER APPLE BUTTER BRIE.
I KNEW SHE COULD COOK,
BUT I DIDN'T KNOW HOW WELL.
I GOT A BRICK BURGER,
A CUBAN AND A MEAT LOAF DOWN.
IT'S ALWAYS GOT A LOT
OF FLAIR AND SPICE AND FLAVOR.
CUBAN CHICKEN SANDWICH.
YOU CAN TELL
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE.
YOU GUYS REALLY HAVE THE TIME
TO DO ALL THIS KIND OF STUFF?
WE MAKE THE TIME.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO US
THAT THINGS TASTE GOOD.
LIKE THIS HEAVY HITTER...
FABULOUS MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
(woman) THE PIECE OF MEAT LOAF
IS JUST WONDERFUL.
IT'S BETTER THAN MOM'S.
AND SCRATCH-MADE...
(Sheri) I GOT MEAT LOAF.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE KETCHUP.
CHIPOTLE KETCHUP--KILLER.
I'M A FAN.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
CHIPOTLE KETCHUP.
GREAT.
FIRST SOME OLIVE OIL.
WE SAUTé THE ONIONS,
SALT AND PEPPER.
SO THE ONIONS HAVE SWEATED?
WE ADD APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
BROWN SUGAR,
CHIPOTLE PEPPER,
CHIPOTLE PEPPER SAUCE.
WHICH IS CALLED...
$5 QUESTION.
ADOBO.
VERY NICE.
TOMATO PASTE.
WOR-CHESTER-SHIRE...
WORCHES--
WHAT IS THE WORD?
I CAN COOK,
BUT I CAN'T SAY THAT.
JUST SAY, "WOR..."
"WOR..."
"CHE-CHE-CHE-CHE."
WOR-CHE-CHE-CHE-CHE.
THEN WE MIX THIS UP.
AND THEN WE ADD
THE PURéED TOMATOES.
SO NO KETCHUP
GOES IN THIS.
THIS IS ALL YOU JUST
DOIN' IT YOUR WAY.
RIGHT.
WE LIKE TO DO IT OUR WAY.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE GET ALL THAT MIXED IN.
SMELLS GREAT. LET THIS
SIT THERE AND SIMMER?
AN HOUR, AN HOUR AND A HALF.
NOW THAT IT'S SIMMERED,
FRESH-SQUEEZED LIME JUICE.
A LITTLE BRIGHTNESS,
A LITTLE ACID.
BREAK DOWN THE ONIONS,
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
I JUST WANT TO TASTE THAT
BY ITSELF. WHOA.
I LIKE THAT.
THAT'S GOOD KETCHUP.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND THIS IS FOR
THE MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
YES.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
MEAT LOAF.
I MAKE IT ALL IN THE SAME PAN
THAT I'M GONNA COOK IT IN.
SEVEN EGGS...
THAT'S A LOT
OF LIQUID CHICKEN.
HOMEMADE MARINARA, ONIONS.
SO THIS IS A GIGANTIC
DUMP-AND-STIR.
YEAH.
I LOVE THE RYE BREAD.
I HAVEN'T SEEN THAT ONE.
IT'S SUCH DELICIOUS BREAD.
ADD A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE,
PARSLEY ALSO.
SOME PEPPER.
WE MIX ALL OF THIS UP.
I CAN GET MY FOOT
IN THERE IF YOU NEED ME TO.
AND THEN 10 POUNDS
OF GROUND CHUCK.
MIX THAT ALL UP
THOROUGHLY.
FORM THE GRANDE LOAF.
WRAP IT IN FOIL.
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMPERATURE?
425, ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
WE REMOVE THE FOIL...
THE LAST HALF-HOUR.
LET IT GET ALL NICE AND CRUSTY
BROWN ON THE OUTSIDE.
YEAH. OKAY?
YEAH. NOW THAT GOES
ON THE FLATTOP?
ON THE FLATTOP.
WILL YOU HAND ME
THE OIL? ALL RIGHT.
HAND THAT THING?
BIG, SLIPPERY BOTTLE.
I ALMOST DID DROP IT.
PUT THIS ON THE FLAT TOP.
I LET IT GET KINDA CRUNCHY
ON BOTH SIDES.
DIG IT.
GET OUR BREAD TOASTED.
WHEAT BERRY BREAD.
AND THEN WE GET PEPPER JACK
CHEESE ON IT. COVER IT.
GET A LITTLE WATER UNDER THERE,
MELT THE CHEESE.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE TALKIN' ABOUT.
THAT'S OUR MEAT LOAF.
NICE AND EASY. THERE YOU GO.
(whistles)
AND THEN WE TAKE SOME
OF THE CHIPOTLE KETCHUP.
NICE.
ALL RIGHT,
GET THAT OTHER PIECE.
THERE WE GO. CUT IT.
THE BRICK'S MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
WAS THE NAME "BRICK" JUST
BECAUSE OF THE SIZE OF THIS?
(laughs)
MMM, THAT'S A GOOD MOVE.
THAT'S A REAL GOOD MOVE.
THE MEAT LOAF HAS GOT
REALLY NICE TEXTURE.
THE RYE BREAD REALLY PLAYS
IN NICELY. MMM. THAT'S CRAZY.
THE CHIPOTLE KETCHUP
CARRIES THE TORCH FOR THIS.
BUT THE WHEAT BERRY BREAD
REALLY DOES GIVE NICE CRUNCH,
A WHOLESOMENESS TO IT.
GOOD JOB,
"MISS CHIPOTLE KETCHUP."
'CAUSE THAT'S JUST
HOW WE DO IT.
HERE'S YOUR MEAT LOAF
WITH SWEET POTATO FRIES.
I DIG IT. IT'S A LAST-MEAL
SANDWICH, YOU KNOW?
MOIST AND SPICY
AND CRUSTY BREAD.
THEIR MEAT LOAF IS SOME
OF THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
THE CHIPOTLE KETCHUP,
I THINK, IS THE KICKER.
I THINK SO, TOO.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
CAROLINA.
WE GOT A CAROLINA.
THE FOOD'S ALWAYS
BEEN WONDERFUL.
I LOVE EVERYTHING.
YOU COME HERE TO EAT,
YOU'RE GONNA BE HAPPY.
TURKEY FLORENTINE.
AND IT'S NOT JUST THE FOOD,
IT'S THE ATMOSPHERE.
SEE YOUR FRIENDS PLAY
SOME MUSIC,
AND HAVE A MEAT LOAF SANDWICH,
AND IT'S A GOOD NIGHT.
EXCELLENT JOB. IT'S QUAINT.
IT'S GOT GOOD ENERGY.
YOU'RE HERE,
MAKE THE FOOD YOURSELF.
SEE, WHAT MORE
COULD YOU ASK FOR?
IT'S THE BOMB.
IT'S THE BRICK.
UP NEXT...
BUFFALO WINGS WITH FRIES.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO D.C...
(man) SHRIMP AND GRITS.
FOR SOUL FOOD...
THIS IS REAL-DEAL
GRITS RIGHT HERE.
WITH ATTITUDE.
"SUPER GRANDMA'S" GRAVY.
I'M ON THE CORNER
OF TENTH AND U STREET
IN MIDTOWN D.C.
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S SERVIN' SOUL FOOD.
NOW I HEAR IT'S JUST NOT
THE AVERAGE, EVERYDAY SOUL FOOD.
I HEAR IT'S THE KIND OF FOOD
THAT'S GONNA MAKE YOU GO
OOH AND AHH.
I GUESS THAT'S WHY THEY NAMED IT
OOHHS & AAHHS.
THIS RIGHT HERE?
THAT'S SOUL, SOUL FOOD.
SOUL, SOUL FOOD.
(woman) FRIED CHICKEN.
FRIED CHICKEN--
THE BEST.
LOVE THE BLACKENED CATFISH.
NINE YEARS IN THE NFL.
LaMONT JORDAN,
YOU ARE THE MAN.
WHEN YOU COME HOME,
THIS IS WHERE YOU HANG OUT?
DEFINITELY, UH, ONE OF
MY FAVORITE PLACES TO COME.
(man) MY FAVORITE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THE BEEF RIBS.
THE FLAVOR IS PHENOMENAL.
(woman) GRAVY
ON THE MEAT LOAF.
THIS AIN'T GRANDMA'S GRAVY.
THIS IS "SUPER GRANDMA'S" GRAVY.
ACTUALLY, IT'S OJI ABBOTT'S
GRANDMA'S GRAVY...
WAITIN' FOR A PLATE.
THAT HE'S BEEN SERVIN' UP
SINCE HE AND HIS FRIEND
INDIA WILSON...
FRIED CATFISH.
POOLED THEIR FAMILY RECIPES.
MY MOM WOULD COOK,
OR HIS GRANDMOTHER--
SHE WAS A GREAT COOK.
WE OPENED UP AND WENT FOR IT.
MAKIN' GRANDMA'S CLASSICS
LIKE THIS ONE.
THE SHRIMP AND GRITS.
WHEN I COME TO D.C.,
I NEED THAT.
IT'S GRIT TIME.
YOU THINK I GOT THIS BODY JUST
FROM EATIN' VEGETABLES
ALL THE TIME. I AM
A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL. MMM.
SO WE GOT
THE WATER SIMMERING?
FIRST THING WE ADD
IS A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM.
I LIKE YOUR DEFINITION
OF "LITTLE BIT."
SALT?
SALT AND THE TINIEST BIT
OF SUGAR.
WOW.
ADD SOME BUTTER. WE'RE GONNA
ADD ALL THIS BUTTER.
THE FAT CAME
RIGHT TO THE TOP THERE.
WHISK IN YOUR GRITS SO THAT
THEY DON'T STICK TOGETHER.
LET THESE SIMMER?
20 MINUTES OR SO.
THE GRITS ARE COOKIN'.
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
SOME SHRIMP?
GOTTA CLEAN YOUR SHRIMP.
YOU DON'T BRING 'EM IN
PRE-PEELED OR PRE-DEVEINED.
NO.
YOU DO ALL THE EXTRA WORK.
GOING TO DO
THE EXTRA MILE,
'CAUSE IT ALWAYS COMES OUT
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR CAJUN SEASONING--
ONION POWDER, GARLIC POWDER
OLD BAY SEASONING,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
CHILI POWDER,
GROUND GINGER...
I LIKE THAT CALL.
AND SOME RED PEPPER FLAKES
FOR SOME HEAT.
BLEND ALL THIS TOGETHER.
OKAY, AND THEN WE'LL ADD THIS
GENEROUSLY TO THE SHRIMP.
WHY NOT JUST TOSS IT
IN A BOWL?
MY GRANDMA WOULD PROBABLY
BEAT ME IF I DID IT DIFFERENT.
(laughs)
SO NOW THAT THOSE ARE SEASONED,
GO OVER TO THE GRILL.
FLATTOP.
AND WE'LL ADD SOME BUTTER
TO THE HOT GRILL,
ADD OUR SHRIMP.
I'M DOWN HERE
CHECKIN' THE GRITS.
YEAH, YOU GOTTA
STIR THOSE PUPPIES,
MAKE SURE THEY DON'T STICK.
GOOD-LOOKIN' GRITS.
CREAMY GRITS.
(whistles)
AND THEN WE'LL ADD SHRIMP
ON TOP OF HERE.
HOW MANY SHRIMP
IN AN ORDER, BOSS?
TEN.
THAT'S A NICE SERVIN'.
LOOK AT THAT.
I'M TRYIN' TO GET AFTER
ONE OF THESE SHRIMP.
MMM. OH, MAN.
YOU GET THE HEAT
AND THE SPICINESS
AND THE SAVORY COMIN'
FROM THE SHRIMP.
MMM. AND THE CREAMY, SALTY
TEXTURE OF THE GRITS...
YOU GOTTA DO IT
THE RIGHT WAY.
ALL RIGHT, SHRIMP.
THEN SHOVEL IN
A MOUTHFUL OF GRITS.
MMM, THIS IS
REAL-DEAL GRITS RIGHT HERE.
GRANDMA WOULD BE PROUD
OF THAT, MAN. NICE JOB, BUD.
THANK YOU.
(Oji) SHRIMP AND GRITS
COMIN' UP.
SHRIMP AND GRITS,
WHICH IS MY FAVORITE.
BIG SHOUT OUT TO OJI.
HE CHEFS IT UP.
NEED ONIONS
AND PEPPERS, PLEASE.
BEST PART ABOUT
THIS PLACE RIGHT HERE
IS THEY HAVE A LARGE
VARIETY OF THINGS.
'CAUSE OJI WILL TRY
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING.
WHATEVER STUFFED,
ADD IT TO THE MENU.
TERIYAKI SALMON.
OH, MAN.
IT'S ONE OF THEM THINGS.
(man) CRAB CAKES,
TENDER AND LIGHT.
YOU CAN SEE IT FLAKES RIGHT OFF.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
BUT HIS SIDES...
(Oji) CABBAGE GREENS
AND MACARONI.
ARE STRAIGHT UP OLD-SCHOOL.
THE CORN BREAD--
OH, MY GOODNESS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I SEND EVERYONE HERE
SPECIFICALLY FOR
THE MAC AND CHEESE.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. IT IS SO CHEESY.
DO YOU SEE ANY MAC
IN THERE?
I'VE EATEN
EVERYTHING IN HERE.
THE FOOD IS GREAT. BEEN COMIN'
HERE SINCE THEY'VE BEEN OPEN.
BACK WHEN THEY WERE
ONLY DOIN' WINGS...
CHICKEN WINGS
UP FRONT, PLEASE.
WHICH ARE STILL
THEIR TOP SELLER.
LET'S TALK
ABOUT CHICKEN WINGS.
OJI'S?
HEY, CAN'T BEAT IT.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN, MAN.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
LEMON PEPPER.
THEN WE'LL ADD
INTO THE FLOUR...
WOW, A LOT OF IT.
BASIL, GOT SOME OREGANO.
STRAIGHT UP OREGANO, OR IS
THAT ITALIAN SEASONING?
JUST A LITTLE OREGANO MIX.
THEN WE GOT SOME GARLIC POWDER.
WE GOT SOME ONION POWDER.
THEN, LIKE,
MIX IT WITH YOUR HAND.
YOU MIX IT WITH YOUR FOOT,
THEY AIN'T GONNA COME BACK.
THEN ONCE WE DO THAT,
TAKE A FEW OF THESE
NICE WINGS HERE,
AND WE'LL DREDGE 'EM.
GOTTA MIX IT UP GOOD.
SHAKE 'EM OFF.
ADD 'EM TO THE BASKET.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
OIL'S AT 350?
350.
READY? HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT, GOLDEN-BROWN
AND DELICIOUS.
AND WHEN IT'S SAUCE TIME...
BUFFALO WINGS READY.
OJI'S DOIN' HIS FROM SCRATCH.
MESSY, AND THEY'RE
REALLY DELICIOUS.
NOW IT'S WING SAUCE TIME?
NOW IT'S WING SAUCE TIME.
ALL RIGHT.
ADD A LITTLE HOT SAUCE...
I LIKE YOUR DEFINITION
OF "A LITTLE."
AND A LITTLE BUTTER.
OKAY, LEMON JUICE,
BASIL-OREGANO BLEND HERE,
SOME SUGAR, AND SOME
GARLIC POWDER.
(whistles)
MIX THIS AROUND,
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
YOU FROM NEW YORK?
NOPE, FROM
WASHINGTON, D .C.
WHY'D YOU SAY "WAD-DAH"?
(laughs)
A LITTLE BIT OF "WAD-DAH."
WE'LL STIR IT.
YOU CAN GET ALL SLOPPY
WITH IT THAT WAY
WHEN YOU'VE GOT
A RED CHEF COAT ON.
YEAH. THOROUGHLY BLEND IT.
OKAY.
TURN OUR HEAT UP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR WINGS.
I USUALLY LET IT BOIL UP
A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN READY TO ROCK.
MY MOUTH IS ALREADY
STARTIN' TO WATER.
PLATE THESE UP.
DON'T THOSE LOOK NICE?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
MMM.
THIS RIGHT HERE--
THIS IS THAT NICE BALANCE
BETWEEN HOT, AND THERE'S
SOME GARLIC,
LITTLE BIT OF THAT
LEMON JUICE COMIN' THROUGH.
MMM, I'M GONNA BE
HONEST WITH YOU.
I DON'T LIKE
BREADED BUFFALO WINGS.
I DON'T LIKE 'EM ANYWHERE...
EXCEPT FOR HERE.
MMM, KNOCKIN' THIS OUT,
MAN.
THAT WING SAUCE--
YOU SHOULD BOTTLE THAT.
BUFFALO WINGS AND FRIES
COMIN' OUT.
THE BUFFALO WINGS ARE
PRETTY SPICY.
KIND OF SULTRY
TASTE TO THEM,
WHICH MADE 'EM
REALLY, REALLY GOD.
I WANT A CRUNCH
TO MEAT RATIO, 50/50.
THE SOUL FOOD FRIED CHICKEN
HERE--BEST IN TOWN.
(India) FRIEND CATFISH.
THE FISH, THE CHICKEN--
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
IF YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR A GOOD MEAL,
OOHHS & AAHHS
IS DEFINITELY THE PLACE.
FRIED CRAB CAKE
AND FRENCH FRIES.
SOUL, SOUL FOOD.
WHEN YOU COME TO D.C.,
YOU GOTTA CHECK THIS SPOT OUT.
THE WINGS ARE PRETTY GANGSTER.
THE WINGS WITH THAT SAUCE.
BUFFALO WINGS
AND FRIES.
THAT'S AWESOME.
GOOD JOB, YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADIN'
TO MASSACHUSETTS...
LOBSTER ROLLS.
WHERE THE COASTAL CLASSICS...
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
ARE SMOKIN'.
THAT IS TOTALLY LEGIT.
I'M ABOUT 30 MINUTES
NORTH OF BOSTON
IN THE FAMOUS TOWN
OF SALEM, MASSACHUSETTS,
YOU KNOW, THE WITCH TRIALS
AND EVERYTHING?
WELL, RIGHT NOW,
I'M IN THE HISTORIC AREA
KNOWN AS ARTISTS' ROW,
AND WHAT CAUGHT MY EAR
IS I HEAR THERE'S A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S MAKIN' A WICKED
LOBSTER MARTINI.
THIS IS THE LOBSTER SHANTY.
(woman) TWO LOBSTERTINIS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
IT'S GREAT. YOU NEVER
SEE IT ANYWHERE ELSE.
(woman) ENJOY.
IT'S LIKE A DIRTY MARTINI,
BUT NOT AS SALTY.
LOBSTER÷ CLAWS.
I'M A LITTLE WARY.
(laughs)
BUT I WILL TRY IT...
LATER, AFTER THE FOOD.
AND A LOBSTER ROLL.
THE BEST I'VE HAD
IN NEW ENGLAND.
(woman) STEAMERS.
EVERYTHING YOU'D EXPECT IN
A NEW ENGLAND SEAFOOD SHACK...
(woman) CLAM BASKET.
AND SOME THINGS
YOU WOULDN'T.
(woman) MARGHERITA PIZZA.
MAC AND CHEESE.
OH, SO GOOD.
THEY'RE SERVING
COMFORT FOOD.
GOIN' IN.
EVER SINCE DIANE WOLF--
HER FRIENDS CALL HER "DEEDEE"--
OVEN'S OPEN.
BOUGHT THE JOINT
THREE AND A HALF YEARS AGO.
YOU GOT IT.
HOW DID YOU FIND
THE LOCATION?
WE WERE ACTUALLY
REGULARS HERE.
(woman) DEEDEE IS ACTUALLY
A TRAINED CHEF
AND GETTING REALLY
WONDERFUL RECIPES.
LIKE THIS NON-NEW ENGLAND
SPECIALTY.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
THIS IS THE BOMB.
IT'S AWESOME.
VERY NICE BARBECUED FLAVOR.
SMOKIN' CHIPS.
WHAT DO WE GOT?
2 PARTS HICKORY,
1 PART MESQUITE.
SOAK THESE IN COFFEE
AND BEER.
REALLY?
AND I'LL LET
THIS SIT OVERNIGHT,
AND LET THE WOOD CHIPS GET
NICE AND SOFT.
TAKE THAT LIQUID OUT. PUT
THE WOOD CHIPS IN THE SMOKER.
ADD SOME HUMIDITY
INSIDE THE SMOKER.
SHE DOESN'T STOP.
ADD THE FLAVOR.
KEEP THE MEAT FROM DRYING OUT.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE SOME SALT MIX.
COARSE GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT,
ROSEMARY, SAGE,
AND PARSLEY GROUND TOGETHER.
OKAY, AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA SMOKE SOME MEAT.
BONELESS PORK BUTT.
START WITH
MAKIN' SOME PORK RUB--
STEAK SEASONING, BROWN SUGAR...
SOME OF YOUR SUPER SALT.
RED PEPPER FLAKES,
CUMIN.
CAYENNE.
LOVE THE SMOKED
HUNGARIAN PAPRIKA,
MILD CHILI POWDER.
PUT THAT LID ON THERE,
AND GET FUNKY WITH IT.
NICE.
GRAB THE SPICES OUT
WITH ONE HAND.
MM-HMM.
RUB IT ON WITH THE OTHER HAND
SO YOU DON'T PUT THE PORK HAND
BACK IN TO CONTAMINATE.
OH, YEAH. PUT IT RIGHT
INTO THE SMOKER, 13 HOURS.
LIKE WE'RE MAKIN'
A WITCH'S BREW.
WE GOTTA BE DOIN'
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE ABSOLUTELY ARE.
A LITTLE GARLIC OIL,
OUR MAGICAL SALT MIX,
DICED ONIONS,
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC...
THAT'S MY STYLE.
(cackles)
BROWN SUGAR.
NOW THAT
THAT IS CARAMELIZED...
A BOATLOAD OF KETCHUP.
THROW IN...
MOLASSES.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
RICE WINE VINEGAR...
INTERESTING.
ORANGE JUICE, PINEAPPLE JUICE,
CHOPPED TOMATOES RIGHT NOW,
CHILI GARLIC PASTE,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
SMOKED PAPRIKA, CINNAMON,
RED PEPPER FLAKES,
CHILI POWDER, CUMIN,
AND THE DEADLY
GHOST CHILI POWDER.
HANG ON.
WHOA!
THEY'RE REALLY HOT.
THEY'RE--
SEE MY EYES?
THERE YOU GO.
GHOST CHILIES.
COOK THIS FOR PROBABLY
ABOUT AN HOUR.
LITTLE IMMERSION
BLENDER INTO THAT.
AND MAKE IT SMOOTH.
LET ME TASTE
THE WICKED BREW.
IS IT READY? MMM.
OOH, A LITTLE KISS
RIGHT THERE AT THE END.
YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE THESE
PORK BUTTS OUT OF THE SMOKER.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU KNOW IT'S DONE WHEN YOU JUST
GRAB A CORNER OF IT LIKE THAT
AND JUST SHRED IT OFF.
MMM. WOW.
DELICIOUS. GREAT RUB.
PULL IT APART.
RIGHT. WE'RE GONNA SAUCE
THE MEAT IN THE BOWL.
GET IT ON... (whistles)
STIR THAT AROUND.
LET'S MAKE THAT SANDWICH,
ALL RIGHT?
LETTUCE AND TOMATO.
(whistles)
WHOA, THAT'S TOTALLY LEGIT.
THE PULLED PORK
IS DELICIOUS.
CRAZY SMOKE WITH THE BEER
AND THE COFFEE.
TENDER, IT'S MOIST,
BUT WHAT REALLY MAKES IT--
YOU'VE GOT A REALLY NICE
SWEET HEAT BARBECUE SAUCE
GOIN' ON THAT COMPLEMENTS IT
INCREDIBLY WELL.
MMM.
SERIOUSLY, GREAT JOB.
ROCK ON.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
SWEET, SPICY AND SALTY.
IT ALL BLENDS WELL
TOGETHER.
OH, IT'S THE BEST.
ENJOY YOUR MEALS.
I LOVE IT HERE.
YOU'RE IN A LITTLE SHACK.
BIG TOURIST AREA.
MM-HMM.
YOU COULD JUST BE SERVING
CORNED BEEF SANDWICHES
AND LOBSTER CHOWDER
AND BE DONE WITH IT.
WHERE'S THE LOVE
IN THAT?
YOU WALK IN, AND YOU GET
REALLY GREAT FOOD.
EVERYTHING IS FRESHLY
PREPARED.
THAT'S WHY PEOPLE COME HERE.
FOR EVERYTHING FROM CLAM
CHOWDER TO FRIED MOZZARELLA...
TO DIE FOR.
EVEN BEEF...
WHEN I'M AT THE LOBSTER SHANTY,
I DO GO FOR THE STEAK TIPS.
FLAT STEAK MARINATED IN STOUT.
GUINNESS STEAK TIPS.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA
START ON FIRST?
I'M GONNA TRIM
THE FLAT MEAT.
NOW THIS IS ALL TRIMMED OFF.
I'M GONNA CUBE IT UP.
BIG CHUNKS LIKE THAT.
NOW THE MARINADE.
BROWN SUGAR,
AND JUST A PINCH--
SOME OF YOUR SUPER SALT.
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
SOME?
A LITTLE SOY SAUCE.
OKAY, A LOT OF SOY SAUCE.
OF COURSE, BLACK PEPPER,
GARLIC CLOVES,
RED PEPPER FLAKES...
WHOA.
GUINNESS.
(together) NICE SOUND.
YES.
I LOVE THE SOUND.
IT'S THE BEST SOUND.
BOATLOAD OF STOUT BEER.
YES, BUT WAIT.
THERE'S MORE.
OKAY.
AND THEN MOLASSES.
WHAT A WILD CONCOCTION.
POUR THE MARINADE
OVER THE MEAT.
SO WE LET THIS GO
FOR AT LEAST EIGHT HOURS.
GRILLS' HOT.
THROW IT ON THE GRILL.
LOOK HOW IT'S STARTED TO BREAK
DOWN ALREADY FROM THE MARINADE.
NICE.
WE ARE READY.
LET'S PLATE THESE UP.
ALL RIGHT. LOOKS GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. REALLY TASTY.
YOU GET ALL THE NOTES.
THE SOY, YOU GET THE BEGINNING
OF THE MOLASSES,
TINY BIT OF HEAT.
THE UNDERLYING THEME HAS
TO BE THAT STOUT BEER.
DON'T JUST THINK THAT
WE'RE A LOBSTER SHACK.
WE MAKE GOOD STEAK, TOO.
MMM. WELL DONE.
EXCELLENT.
STEAK TIPS ARE DELICIOUS,
CUT RIGHT APART.
IT'S JUST GOOD FOOD.
IT'S NOT PRETENTIOUS.
(Diane) SURF & TURF.
IT HAS SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE.
WE HAD THE MARINATED FLAT MEAT
DONE IN THE STOUT BEER,
THE REAL DEAL BARBECUE,
BUT THE WHOLE REASON
I ROLLED INTO THIS JOINT
WAS I HEARD ABOUT
THIS LOBSTER MARTINI.
TASTES LIKE THE OCEAN.
LOVELY.
YOU NEVER SEE IT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
WHEN AM I GONNA TRY THAT?
HOW ABOUT NOW?
HOW ABOUT
WHEN WE COME BACK?
BOILED LOBSTER.
AT THE LOBSTER SHANTY
IN SALEM, MASSACHUSETTS...
SET UP IN A MINUTE.
CHEF DIANE WOLF IS DOIN'
LOBSTER ANY WAY YOU WANT IT...
LOBSTER PIE. WE DO SELL
TONS OF LOBSTER.
LOBSTER ROLL.
IT'S THE WAY IT SHOULD BE.
IT'S JUST GREAT.
LOBSTER MAC AND CHEESE,
MMM, IT'S FANTASTIC.
THERE'S NOTHING
LIKE FRESH LOBSTER.
YEAH,
ESPECIALLY IN A MARTINI.
(Diane) LOBSTERTINI.
I LOVE MARTINIS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
IT'S SOMETHING
I HAVE NEVER HAD BEFORE.
THANKS TO BAR MANAGER
SARAH STELLATO.
TWO LOBSTERTINIS.
YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT INVENTED THIS, RIGHT?
YEAH, INSTEAD OF VERMOUTH,
LOBSTER ESSENCE,
AND PUT A CLAW IN IT.
AND THEY LIKE IT?
YEAH, THEY LIKE IT.
IT TASTES LIKE THE OCEAN.
LOVELY.
I WANTED TO GET A DRINK
AND ENJOY LOBSTER,
SO YOU HAVE TO
GO WITH THIS.
THESE ARE THE LOBSTERS.
WE'RE GONNA USE THEIR BODIES TO
MAKE THE STOCK--THE ESSENCE
FOR THE LOBSTERTINI.
STILL A LITTLE
FUNK-AFIED BY THIS
TO BE VERY HONEST
WITH YOU.
I MEAN, I LIKE--I LOVE
MAKIN' LOBSTER BISQUE.
SAME START,
DIFFERENT FINISH.
DO YOU LIKE
DIRTY MARTINIS?
I LIKE DIRTY MARTINIS.
THEN I THINK THIS IS
GONNA BE YOUR SEGUE.
THIS IS GONNA DO IT?
LIKE SALTY, BRINY,
DELICIOUS LOBSTER FLAVOR.
LOBSTER?
IT'S ALSO A SNACK.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
AND, OF COURSE, WE THREW SOME
OF OUR MAGICAL SALT MIX
IN THE WATER.
OF COURSE WE DID,
'CAUSE WE DON'T DO ANYTHING
WITHOUT THE MAGICAL
SALT MIX.
NOTHING.
LET THOSE COOK FOR ABOUT
10 TO 15 MINUTES.
TILL THEY TURN RED.
BRING 'EM OUT, LET 'EM COOL
DOWN, CRACK 'EM,
TAKE THE MEAT AND BEGIN
THE PROCESS OF MAKING THE BROTH
WITH THE LOBSTER SHELL.
YES.
COLD WATER,
GOT THE BODIES...
YEP.
IN ALL THEIR GOODNESS.
BLACK PEPPERCORNS, ONION,
CARROT, CELERY...
A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
FRESH ROSEMARY,
FRESH DILL...
DILL AND A LITTLE
SAGE.
AND SAGE.
SIMMER THIS
FOR FIVE HOURS.
HOW YOU GONNA KEEP
THE MURKINESS OF IT OUT?
STRAIN IT ONCE THROUGH
A REGULAR CHINOIS.
STRAINER.
THEN I'LL RUN IT AGAIN THROUGH,
LIKE, A COFFEE FILTER
TO GET ALL OF THAT SEDIMENT
OUT OF IT.
SO THIS IS JUST
CLEAR LOBSTER BROTH.
MM-HMM. STRAIN IT
INTO A SQUEEZE BOTTLE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE LOBSTER MARTINI.
OH, WE'RE NOT GOING TO.
I AM GONNA HAND YOU OFF
TO SARAH, MY BAR MANAGER.
I'M A LITTLE WARY.
(laughs)
DO YOU WANT ME TO MAKE IT?
ARE YOU READY?
OH, GO FOR IT.
VODKA.
HEALTHY POUR.
YEP.
LOBSTER ESSENCE,
A LITTLE BIT MORE THAN
YOU WOULD DO VERMOUTH
IN A MARTINI.
BUT IT'S NOT AS STRONG.
DOESN'T HAVE A TASTE
LIKE VERMOUTH.
THEN YOU JUST SHAKE IT.
DOES ANYBODY FEEL
LIKE I'M GONNA BE HAVING
A COLD LOBSTER BISQUE
COCKTAIL?
CHILLED MARTINI GLASS.
STRAIN IT.
LOBSTER CLAW,
THE LEMON TWIST.
THERE'S YOUR LOBSTERTINI.
LET ME PREPARE MYSELF.
IS THERE A WAY TO DO THIS
IN PARTICULAR?
SOME PEOPLE PUT
THE LOBSTER IN THE GLASS.
SOME PEOPLE JUST EAT
THE LOBSTER AND THEY FINISH IT
WITH A SIP OF THE MARTINI...
MM-HMM.
WHICH IS WHAT I
PREFER TO DO.
WHEN IN ROME...
MMM, GREAT LOBSTER FLAVOR.
THIS IS ALMOST LIKE
THE GHOST OF LOBSTER MARTINI.
YEAH.
WHERE YOU DON'T GET THE LOBSTER,
YOU JUST GET THE FLAVOR.
YOU JUST GET THE HINT
OF IT, SO I UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU SERVE THE--
THE CLAW WITH IT.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT? I THINK THAT
PEOPLE THAT REALLY LIKE MARTINIS
AND LIKE 'EM DIRTY,
THAT'S GOT IT.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY
LOBSTER MARTINI.
IT'S FRESH AND GOT
SOME LEMON IN IT. IT'S GOOD.
I'D DEFINITELY HAVE IT AGAIN.
YOU NEVER SEE IT ANYWHERE ELSE.
ENJOY.
JUST LOVE IT HERE.
IT'S A COOL PLACE
TO COME TO.
THE LOBSTER
MAC AND CHEESE.
AND THE FOOD IS FABULOUS.
SO THAT'S IT
FROM THE LOBSTER SHANTY
IN SALEM, MASSACHUSETTS.
A LOBSTER COCKTAIL.
I'VE ALWAYS TOLD YOU,
IF IT'S FUNKY,
WE'LL FIND IT.
SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(banging pans rhythmically)