HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(woman) NOW WE'RE GONNA
BREAK DOWN THE PORK LOIN.
THIS IS OFFERED
IN A SANDWICH?
WELL, YEAH. YOU BET.
SANDWICHES...
MMM!
PLUS...
SALTY POTATO BALLS.
THEY SOAK 'EM IN BRINE.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
26, PLEASE.
THE '30s-ERA DRUGSTORE...
TACOS.
DOIN' A HANDMADE REUBEN...
YOU KNOCKED THAT ONE OUT.
AND A KILLER QUESADILLA...
WHOA! REALLY GOOD.
IN MINNEAPOLIS...
THE FOOD IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
THE LOCAL CAFE...
BEST-KEPT SECRET.
PILIN' ON THE PORK...
PORK SANDWICH.
AND MAKIN' A MOUNTAIN
OF MEATLOAF...
MMM! THAT'S CHRISTMAS
IN A SANDWICH.
AND IN
NORTH WILDWOOD, NEW JERSEY...
CAN I GET
A HORSEY IN CHICAGO?
THE HOT DOG JOINT...
NO GUTS, NO GLORY.
THAT YOU...
MOST FUN PLACE FOR A HOT DOG.
COULDN'T WAIT TO SHOW ME.
THIS IS THE BEST.
THIS IS THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
'CAUSE I MADE IT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
NOW YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE "D,"
I AM A BIG FAN
OF THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST,
SO IT'S ALWAYS GREAT
TO BE BACK HERE.
THIS TIME WE'RE ROLLING
THROUGH SPOKANE
IN AN OLD-SCHOOL AREA
KNOWN AS BROWNE'S ADDITION
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT'S
GOT KIND OF AN ECLECTIC SPIN
ON TRADITIONAL PUB FOOD.
THIS IS THE ELK PUBLIC HOUSE.
THE MUSHROOM SACCHETTI.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
THERE'S THE PORK BURRITA.
THIS PUB DOES IT
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
YUM!
IT'S A MAINSTAY.
EVERYONE WILL DRIVE
FROM ALL AROUND TO GET HERE.
THANK YOU.
TO SCARF DOWN WHAT OWNER
BRAD FOSSEEN IS CRANKING OUT.
QUESADILLA GOING IN
THE WINDOW.
WE'RE JUST TRYING
TO MAKE EVERYTHING
LIKE IF YOU MADE IT AT HOME.
SAME WAY HE'S BEEN DOING IT
HERE FOR OVER A DECADE...
PERFECT.
SINCE HE SET UP SHOP
IN A 1930s-ERA PHARMACY.
IT'S GOOD.
IT'S JUST GREAT FOOD
DONE FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S READY.
EVEN THE BASICS
LIKE THE REUBEN.
AMAZING.
BEST REUBEN IN TOWN.
THE SAUERKRAUT THAT THEY PUT
ON IT, THEY MAKE IT FRESH HERE.
THE MEAT JUST, AHH,
MELTED IN MY MOUTH.
OKAY, WELL, GIVE US
A RUNDOWN HERE.
ALL RIGHT, PERFECT.
WE JUST TAKE THE CORNED BEEF.
THIS A PRE-BRINED CORNED BEEF.
YES, SIR.
YOU'RE GONNA FORTIFY IT?
WE ARE. YEP.
POUR SOME BEER ON TOP OF IT.
FOR THE REUBEN,
WE GO A LITTLE TRADITIONAL--
THOUSAND ISLAND, KRAUT.
THIS IS COMPLETELY
UNTRADITIONAL.
WITH BEER?
RIGHT.
YEAH.
WELL, WORKS FOR ME.
PEPPERCORNS.
PEPPERCORNS AND BAY LEAF.
CORIANDER.
THAT'S CORIANDER
AND THEN A LITTLE CARAWAY.
AND THEN I JUST GET IN THERE
AND SPREAD IT ALL AROUND,
DISTRIBUTE ALL THE FLAVOR.
HOW MANY TIMES
DO YOU MAKE THIS A WEEK?
20 TIMES.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
WRAP IT UP, IN THE OVEN,
350, 3 1/2 TO 4 HOURS.
YEAH.
DIG IT.
ALL RIGHT. CABBAGE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
SAUERKRAUT FOR THE REUBEN.
THROW THE CABBAGE IN HERE.
PUT IT ALL IN THE POT.
SO THEN WE HAVE SOME
BLACKTHORN CIDER, MALT VINEGAR.
THAT'S IT
ON THE VINEGAR, HUH?
YEAH, 'CAUSE THE BLACKTHORN
GIVES IT MOST OF ITS FLAVOR.
BLACK PEPPER, SALT.
STIR ALL THAT UP.
POP IT ON THE STOVE.
STEAM IT AN HOUR AND 15
UNTIL IT'S NICE AND SIMMERED.
DARK CABBAGE.
THIS IS ALL READY,
NICE AND STEAMED UP
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF COLOR TO IT.
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PULL
THE CORNED BEEF OUT OF THE OVEN
THAT'S BEEN IN THERE
FOR A WHILE.
(whistles)
JUST CUT IT UP.
YOU COULD HAVE DONE THAT
WITH A DRUMSTICK.
LOOK AT THAT, MAN. OH,
I DON'T KNOW? HOT? YOU THINK?
I'M NOT SCARED OF YOU.
OH, DUDE. DELICIOUS.
GOOD.
TOAST UP OUR RYE BREAD
A LITTLE BIT.
PUT A NICE LITTLE PILE
OF MEAT ON THERE, KRAUT ON.
CHOP THAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
PILE THIS UP.
GRAB A LITTLE SWISS. LID IT.
LET IT STEAM FOR A MINUTE.
HE JUST LID IT UP.
WHILE THAT'S STEAMING,
GET A LITTLE THOUSAND ISLAND.
WE MADE OUR OWN--STRAIGHT UP
MAYONNAISE, KETCHUP,
SWEET PICKLES,
AND A LITTLE SALT,
NOTHING TOO CRAZY.
LITTLE BIT HEAVY ON THAT.
HURRY UP
AND SERVE THE SANDWICH
BEFORE I EAT ALL
THE CORNED BEEF ON THE TABLE.
I THINK THAT'S
READY TO ROLL THERE.
BUILD THE SANDWICH,
NICE AND STEAMED UP.
POP THAT ON THERE.
THAT'S OUR REUBEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. KILLER.
THE CORNED BEEF IS SUPER TENDER,
GREAT FLAVOR, ENORMOUS FLAVOR.
NICE BIG SLICES OF DARK RYE,
TOAST THE BREAD
WITHOUT THE BUTTER, I LOVE THAT.
THE NICE HELPING
OF THE THOUSAND ISLAND. MMM.
BUT THE KICKER,
THE SAUERKRAUT--
NOT QUITE A SAUERKRAUT,
KIND OF A COOKED SLAW,
NOT SUPER BITTER,
NOT OVERPOWERING,
NOT OWNING THE DISH.
YOU KNOCKED THAT ONE OUT.
AWESOME.
GLAD YOU ENJOY IT.
I HAVE A REUBEN.
THE CORNED BEEF IS AS TENDER
AS THE SWISS CHEESE.
HOW'S THAT REUBEN
TREATING YA?
IT'S GREAT.
THE SAUERKRAUT ROCKS.
IT'S A REALLY GOOD SANDWICH
EVERY TIME.
YOUR BOWL OF GUMBO.
ANYTHING ON THE MENU,
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
ENJOY.
LOOKS GOOD.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A GOOD FUN PLACE
TO COME DOWN TO.
'CAUSE EVERYBODY HERE
KIND OF KNOWS EACH OTHER.
EVERYBODY HAS A GOOD TIME.
I'LL GET THIS.
WHICH IS BRAD'S WHOLE IDEA.
PEOPLE COME IN AND CHILL,
PUB-STYLE,
AND JUST GET
A GOOD DECENT MEAL.
OKAY, LADIES.
IT'S DEFINITELY PUB FOOD,
BUT KIND OF EXPANDED
ON THAT WHOLE NOTION
OF IT'S GOT TO BE A CERTAIN WAY.
LIKE LAMB SANDWICHES...
TACOS.
PORK AND COLESLAW TACOS...
EVERY TIME I COME HERE
I HAVE TO ORDER IT.
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
BARBECUE CHICKEN
QUESADILLA.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
SMOKED ONION DIP--
THEY SMOKE THEIR OWN ONIONS.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A QUESADILLA.
YEP.
YOU'RE GONNA GO
WITH FULL CHICKENS.
YES.
AND THE REASON BEING?
I THINK YOU JUST GET ALL
THE GOOD FLAVOR OUT OF THE MEAT.
I LIKE IT.
2 1/2-POUND W.O.G.s.
EXACTLY.
2 1/2 POUNDS
IS HOW MUCH THEY WEIGH.
W.O.G.s MEANS
WITHOUT GIBLETS.
JUST GONNA DO OIL,
SALT, AND PEPPER.
GONNA RUB 'EM REAL GOOD.
GET THE SALT AND PEPPER
ALL THE WAY OVER THERE.
POP 'EM IN THE OVEN AT 350
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE GOT
THE FRYERS OUT OF THE OVEN.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S NICE.
SO SHRED IT ALL BY HAND
IN THE BOWL?
YEAH, JUST GET IN THERE.
THIS IS THE WAY
WE LIKE TO DO IT,
'CAUSE YOU GET
THIS NICE DARK MEAT HERE.
LOOK AT ALL THAT FLAVOR.
WE ALWAYS HAVE LOTS OF BONES
AROUND TO MAKE FRESH STOCK.
YOU MAKE ALL YOUR OWN STOCK?
WE DO.
MMM. JUST A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER AND A GOOD ROAST.
SO THAT'S HOW IT BREAKS DOWN.
WHAT ARE WE OFF TO, BRAD?
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE ONIONS
FOR THE SMOKED ONION SAUCE FOR
THE BARBECUE CHICKEN QUESADILLA.
ARE WE GONNA
MILL THE FLOUR, TOO?
WE'RE THINKING ABOUT IT.
OKAY, SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
I'M JUST GONNA GET THESE READY,
POP 'EM IN THE PAN.
HICKORY WOOD CHIPS
IN A HOTEL PAN.
PUT THAT ON TOP.
TO LOCK IT IN.
WE JUST SMOKE 'EM
RIGHT ON THE STOVE.
IT'S GONNA GET SMOKY.
45 MINUTES YOU LET IT ROLL.
DUDE, YOU'RE SERIOUS ABOUT THAT.
LOOK AT THE GREAT SMOKE
ON THAT.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT, MAN.
THOSE ARE SMOKED.
THEY'RE DEFINITELY SMOKED.
THEY KIND OF PURéE BETTER
WHEN THEY'RE A LITTLE WARM.
SO WE HAVE
OUR PURéED SMOKED ONIONS.
THEN WE HAVE SOUR CREAM,
MAYONNAISE.
NOTHING LIKE
A LITTLE FOOD LUBE.
YEAH. (laughs)
A LITTLE MILK,
WOR-CESTER-SHIRE.
WHAT WAS THAT CALLED?
HAVE YOU EVER READ THE LABEL?
WOR-CESTER-SHIRE.
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, SO WE JUST ADDED IN
THE WOR-CESTER-SHIRE.
NICE.
PEPPER AND A LITTLE LIQUID
SMOKE, SUGAR, KOSHER SALT.
THIS IS JUST
FOR THE QUESADILLA?
YEP. IT IS.
DUDE.
(laughs)
STIR IT UP.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WE'LL LET THIS MARRY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE SMOKED ONION SAUCE
IS MADE.
YEAH.
NOW BARBECUE SAUCE?
YOU GOT IT. START OUT WITH
KETCHUP, BROWN SUGAR, HONEY.
WE HAVE A LITTLE LIQUID SMOKE,
CHICKEN STOCK, RED CHILI FLAKES.
JUST STIR THAT UP.
LET THAT JUST SIT THERE
AND SIMMER?
YEP, FOR HALF AN HOUR.
"B-RAD"?
YES, SIR.
WOR-CESTER-SHIRE
IS ACTUALLY WOOS-TER-SHEER.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO GET
ALL HIGH-TECH ON ME. COME ON.
(laughs)
I WAS TOLD
THERE'D BE NO MATH.
(laughs)
I LOVE THIS GUY.
OH, MAN.
I THINK I MIGHT HAVE
PULLED SOMETHING.
OKAY, SO WHAT
ARE WE GONNA DO NOW?
LADLE SOME OF THAT
BARBECUE SAUCE ON THERE,
SOME OF THAT PULLED CHICKEN,
SOME MOZZARELLA,
LITTLE SLICE OF RED ONION,
CILANTRO.
POP IT ON THE FLATTOP.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE LOOKING GOOD.
READY TO CUT IT UP.
OKAY.
SO YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
THE SWEET AND SPICY GOING ON
WITH THE BARBECUE SAUCE
AND THEN THAT GETS DIPPED
INTO THIS SMOKED ONION DIP.
YEP.
WHOA! REALLY GOOD.
THE DIP, THE SMOKE IS NOT THAT
FILLS YOUR NOSE,
PALATE'S SHOT,
CAN'T TASTE ANYTHING ELSE.
STANDARD QUESADILLA,
TOASTED, DONE THE RIGHT WAY
WITH A GOOD AMOUNT OF CHEESE.
FOR A DIP THAT COMPLEMENTS
A QUESADILLA, IT'S NOT A SALSA.
SO THIS TAKES THE WHOLE
QUESADILLA THING
OUT OF THE LATIN FLAIR,
A WHOLE NOTHER DIRECTION.
DUDE, THAT ROCKED.
BARBECUE CHICKEN
QUESADILLA.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
AND I LOVE IT.
IT'S GREAT WITH THE CHICKEN
AND THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
IT'S ITS OWN ECLECTIC MIX.
THE SMOKED ONION SAUCE,
COME ON.
I KNOW. I PUT IT
ON EVERYTHING HERE.
YOU COULD PUT THAT
ON ICE CREAM.
I PUT IT IN MY BEER.
I LOVE MIXING EVERYTHING IN.
I LOVE HANGING OUT HERE.
TABLE 26, PLEASE.
IT'S A STAPLE OF SPOKANE.
IT'S A PLACE YOU WANT
TO COME BACK TO.
TO HANG OUT.
BROTHER, I GOT
TO TELL YOU SOMETHING...
IT WAS A PLEASURE.
FUN PLACE,
PERFECT ATTITUDE,
AND THE FOOD,
YOU DO THINGS THAT INSPIRE YOU.
WE'RE COMING BACK.
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
LOVE TO SEE YOU. THANKS.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADING TO MINNESOTA...
THEY MAKE IT ALL
FROM SCRATCH.
WHERE A TINY JOINT...
YOU MAKE THIS ALSO?
YEAH.
IS CRANKING OUT BIG FLAVOR.
BOTH OF THOSE ARE GOING ON?
YEAH.
MMM. THAT'S CHRISTMAS
IN A SANDWICH.
YOU KNOW THE FUNNY THING
ABOUT TRIPLE "D"
IS THE LOCATION NAMES
DON'T ALWAYS SEEM TO MAKE SENSE.
LIKE IN OMAHA, NEBRASKA,
WE WERE AT CALIFORNIA TACO.
WELL, THEN WE WERE IN
ALBUQUERQUE, NEW MEXICO,
AT THE STANDARD DINER,
AND IT WAS ANYTHING
BUT STANDARD.
THEN WE HAD FERNDALE, MICHIGAN,
AT THE FLY TRAP.
I DIDN'T SEE ONE FLY
IN THE WHOLE PLACE.
SO HERE WE ARE ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF MINNEAPOLIS
AT A JOINT THAT'S ONLY
500 SQUARE FEET,
AND GET THIS, WHAT'S IT CALLED?
THE COLOSSAL CAFE.
I'D LIKE THE SPECIAL.
SURE. WOULD YOU LIKE
SOUP OR SALAD WITH THAT?
SOMETIMES YOU CAN BARELY GET IN
TO PUT IN YOUR ORDER.
(woman) THERE YOU ARE.
THE FOOD
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
HAND 'EM UP.
THEY MAKE IT ALL
FROM SCRATCH.
EVEN THE BREAD
FOR THE TOAST.
SHORT STACK.
WE ABSOLUTELY ALWAYS DIE
FOR THE PANCAKES.
B.L.T.
IT'S THE BEST B.L.T.
IN THE WORLD. MMM.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD.
MINNEAPOLIS'S BEST-KEPT SECRET.
THAT OPENED ONLY
FIVE AND A HALF YEARS AGO...
HOT. BE CAREFUL.
WHEN BESS GIANNAKAKIS
SAW THE POTENTIAL
IN THIS ABANDONED RESTAURANT.
WELL, I JUST HAD A VISION
ABOUT COOKING FOR PEOPLE.
THERE WE GO.
IT SHOULD BE LIKE
THEY CAME INTO MY HOME.
SHIP THAT UP.
SO SHE CASHED IN...
ON ITS WAY.
YOU SOLD ALL YOUR THINGS?
RIGHT.
AND MADE IT HAPPEN.
GOT IT.
SHE'S JUST A WONDERFUL COOK.
ONE MINUTE.
EVERYTHING HAS THAT, LIKE,
MADE-AT-HOME FEEL.
COMING UP HERE.
'CAUSE HER VISION WAS THE KIND
OF FOOD SHE GREW UP WITH--
FRESH AND TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH,
LIKE THIS BEST SELLER.
PORK SANDWICH.
(woman) THE MARINATED
PORK SANDWICH,
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT SHE DOES WITH IT.
YOU JUST CAN'T TASTE IT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
MAKING A MARINADE
FOR THE PORK.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT, SOME GARLIC,
FRESH ROSEMARY.
DO YOU GROW YOUR OWN?
YEAH, IN THE BACKYARD.
SEA SALT...
OREGANO.
OREGANO, DIJON,
BLACK PEPPER--FRESH.
AHA. THIS IS THE ONLY WAY
TO TREAT BLACK PEPPER
IS FRESH GRIND.
MAY I?
BUZZ IT UP.
OKAY, PUT IT IN THERE.
OKAY, NOW THAT'S A PEPPER.
LEMON JUICE, WHITE WINE.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT OFF.
I'VE GOT THE CANOLA OIL HERE.
EMULSIFYING IT.
OKAY.
LET'S POUR THAT IN THERE.
MARINADE?
IT'S SALAD DRESSING.
THAT'S AWESOME.
HEY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA BREAK DOWN
THE PORK LOIN--
SOME BERKSHIRE PORK.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH, YOU BET.
THIS IS ONE
OF THE HEIRLOOM PORKS.
IT'S MARBLED WITH FAT,
TONS OF FLAVOR.
THIS IS OFFERED
IN A SANDWICH?
YEAH.
SO JUST KIND OF CLEAN IT UP.
TIME TO SLICE IT UP.
JUST TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
THAT PORK RIGHT THERE,
THAT'S WINNER, WINNER,
BERKSHIRE DINNER.
OKAY, SO THIS IS GONNA GO
IN THE MARINADE FOR HOW LONG?
THE LONGEST I'VE LET IT
SIT IN THERE IS 24 HOURS.
SO IN THE FRIDGE.
AND THEN WE'VE GOT TO MAKE
THE AIOLI FOR IT ALSO.
OF COURSE, WE DO,
BECAUSE NOTHING COMES
OUT OF A JAR IN THIS PLACE.
OKAY, LEMON ZEST.
SQUEEZES IT UP LIKE THAT
SO THE SEEDS DON'T FALL IN.
LITTLE BIT OF FRESH ROSEMARY,
MAYONNAISE, SOME SOUR CREAM,
SALT, HOT SAUCE.
INTERESTING AIOLI.
MM-HMM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
COOK UP THE PORK.
WHAT KIND OF BREAD
ARE WE SERVING THIS WITH?
THE BAGUETTES THAT I MAKE.
YOU MAKE--REALLY?
YEAH.
WHERE?
RIGHT HERE.
HOW MANY LOAVES
DO YOU BAKE A DAY?
BETWEEN 20 AND 60
DEPENDING ON WHAT'S GOING ON.
DO YOU GO HOME?
YEAH, I DO. I DO.
OKAY, WE READY?
YEP, SO I'M GONNA PULL
THE BREAD OFF.
I'M GONNA ADD SOME GREENS,
THE AIOLI...
OKAY.
AND THE PORK.
THAT'S HEALTHY.
I GOT IT.
TAKE A LOOKIE-LOO AT THAT.
MMM. THAT'S PORK-TASTIC.
(laughs)
LOOK HOW TENDER THAT IS.
BUT TALK ABOUT
FORTIFIED WITH FLAVOR.
THE MARINADE
IS OUT OF BOUNDS. MMM.
THE LEMON AIOLI--
NICE, BRIGHT FRESHNESS TO THAT.
RIGHT.
YOU CAN BAKE.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE BREAD.
IT IS. MMM!
IT'S EVERYTHING I HAVE
RIGHT NOW
NOT TO MOW
THAT WHOLE THING DOWN.
MARINATED PORK SANDWICH.
IF I TAKE A BITE OF THIS THING,
I START TO DROOL. IT'S AWESOME.
SAVORY, IT HAS REALLY EXCELLENT
SPICES ON IT. IT'S FABULOUS.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
IT'S A NEIGHBORHOOD PLACE.
(woman) AWESOME.
WE LOVE THE SPACE. WE LOVE
THE ENERGY THAT'S HERE.
WE LOVE THE FOOD.
COMING UP.
AND THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT BESS WAS GOING FOR.
LITTLE BIT LONGER ON THAT.
SHE'S GOT SOMETHING MAGIC
GOING ON THERE IN THE KITCHEN.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE
YOUR FOOD?
I LIKE TO MAKE IT
ITS OWN LITTLE STYLE
BUT MAKE IT FAMILIAR ENOUGH
SO PEOPLE WILL TRY IT.
LIKE HER SPIN
ON THIS DINER CLASSIC...
(woman) MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
TOPPED WITH A SCRATCH-MADE
CRANBERRY COMPOTE.
(man) ONCE YOU'VE EATEN
THIS MEATLOAF,
YOU DON'T WANT TO EAT MEATLOAF
ANYWHERE ELSE.
GET US GOING.
I'VE GOT SOME CARROTS, ONIONS,
CELERY, FRESH ROMA TOMATOES,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
MIXTURE OF OREGANO
AND BASIL AND THYME.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
GOOD.
I GOT THE VEGGIES HERE, DIJON
MUSTARD, BREADCRUMBS, EGGS.
STIR THIS.
I'M GONNA DO THE BEEF,
THE SAUSAGE THAT I MADE.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN SAUSAGE?
YEAH.
OH, OF COURSE, YOU DO.
ABOUT 1/3 SAUSAGE,
2/3 BEEF.
AND THEN TAKE IT
AND LET IT BROWN.
I'M GONNA ROLL IT UP.
REALLY?
I DON'T WANT IT
TO REALLY "BROWN" BROWN.
I'LL BAKE IT WITH WATER.
SO IT KEEPS THE MOISTURE IN
THE AIR WHILE THIS IS ROASTING
SO IT DOESN'T DRY IT UP.
RIGHT.
BAKE IT FOR
A LITTLE OVER AN HOUR
AND THEN I LET IT SET
IN THE REFRIGERATOR OVERNIGHT,
SO IT CUTS NICELY.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE COMPOTE
FOR THE MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
SO WE GOT CRANBERRIES...
THOSE ARE BIG 'UNS.
GRANNY SMITH APPLE, FRESH
ORANGE JUICE, AND ORANGE RIND,
HONEY, BROWN SUGAR.
OH! YOU LOVE
YOUR BROWN SUGAR.
I DO.
A CINNAMON STICK.
SO WE'RE GONNA
LET THAT COOK DOWN.
OKAY.
PULL IT OUT OF THE REFRIGERATOR
AND UNWRAP IT.
IT'S COOLED.
MM-HMM.
SLICE IT UP.
LOOK HOW DENSE THAT IS.
I LIKE TO USE A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL ON THE GRILL.
GRAB A ROLL.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU BAKED THIS ALSO?
YEAH.
OF COURSE, YOU DO,
'CAUSE THE ELVES
COME IN AT 6:00.
AND JUST HEAT THIS UP.
ROLL.
OH, YOU'RE NOT SERIOUS.
BOTH OF THOSE ARE GOING ON?
YEAH.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE WHEELS ARE ABOUT READY
TO FALL OFF THE BUS
ON THE WAY TO FLAVOR TOWN.
THERE IS NO--
AND THEN COMPOTE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
DO YOU NEED A KNIFE?
NOW THIS
IS JUST SILLINESS.
MMM! THAT'S CHRISTMAS
IN A SANDWICH.
(laughs)
YOU GOT A BALANCE OF FLAVORS
GOING ON THERE.
THE ORANGE ZEST
IN THE COMPOTE--
IS THERE SOME ORANGE ZEST
ALSO IN THE MEAT ITSELF?
IN THE SAUSAGE.
I'M REALLY PICKING UP
THAT NOTE OF THE CITRUS,
WHICH MAKES IT BRIGHT.
YOU BAKE THE BUN.
YOU MAKE THE SAUSAGE.
YOU MAKE IT ALL BY HAND.
I DO NOT KNOW HOW YOU DO IT,
BUT WHAT YOU DO IS PRIME TIME.
GREAT.
MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
THE CRANBERRY SAUCE JUST
KIND OF EXPLODES IN YOUR MOUTH.
(man) IT'S SO FLAVORFUL
AND JUICY.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANOTHER MEATLOAF
SANDWICH YOU'VE EVER HAD.
READY FOR THAT.
SHE JUST DOES A GREAT JOB
PUTTING THE STUFF TOGETHER.
SOMETIMES STUFF
YOU NEVER THINK OF...
(Bess) HOT. HOT. HOT.
APPLE WALNUT BRIE FLAPPERS.
COMING UP.
YOU DON'T USUALLY GET BRIE
ON A PANCAKE.
BUT YOU DO HERE.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
LOOK AT THIS. MMM.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
GOOD TO GO.
FIVE AND A HALF YEARS AGO
AFTER BESS GIANNAKAKIS
HAD AN IDEA...
I HAD JUST THIS VISION IN MY
HEAD OF SOME NEIGHBORHOOD SPOT.
BREAKFAST PLATE.
IT BECAME A REALITY.
THERE YOU ARE.
DEFINITELY
A NEIGHBORHOOD DEAL.
I'D LIKE THE SPECIAL.
AND IT'S THE KIND OF PLACE
WHERE FOLKS JUST WANT
TO START THEIR DAY.
(Bess) FRENCH TOAST BRIOCHE.
IT IS THE BEST BREAKFAST YOU'RE
GONNA HAVE IN MINNEAPOLIS.
BACON, EGG, AND CHEESE.
FROM BREAKFAST SANDWICHES
ON SCRATCH-MADE BISCUITS...
GO AHEAD AND PLATE 'EM UP.
TO SCONES LOADED
WITH GREEN ONIONS, SPINACH,
AND BLUE CHEESE...
OH, MY GOODNESS.
FLAKY, LIGHT, DELICIOUS.
MMM. IT'S JUST A SHAME
THAT SHE RAN OUT OF THEM...
(laughs)
AND SHE DOESN'T HAVE
ANY MORE TO GO FOR YOU.
THERE WE GO.
AND BESS'S TAKE ON PANCAKES.
ABOUT THREE MINUTES
ON THE FLAPPERS.
FLAPPERS?
FLAPPERS.
IS THAT A MINNESOTA THING?
NO, THAT'S A BESS THING.
I CALL IT A FLAPPER.
IT'S A YEAST-BASED PANCAKE.
A YEAST-BASED PANCAKE.
RIGHT.
FLAPPERS ARE THE BOMB.
THEY'RE JUST INCREDIBLE.
APPLE WALNUT BRIE FLAPPERS--
THEY ARE MY FAVORITE.
IT'S AWESOME.
MM-HMM. GO.
ALL RIGHT,
WARM MILK, SUGAR.
LITTLE BIT FOR ME,
SOME FOR YOU.
BRANDY. REALLY?
YEAH. YEAST.
THERE WE GO.
IS THAT BUTTER?
THAT'S EGGS.
WHOA. YOU JUST KEEP...
POURING, JUST KEEP POURING.
TUB O' LIQUID CHICKEN
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S RIGHT, MISTER.
IT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
(whistles)
CLARIFIED BUTTER.
I LOVE
YOUR MEASURING TECHNIQUES.
YOU LIKE THAT?
SOME AND HERE WE GO.
YEAH.
WE HAVE FLOUR, SEA SALT.
SEE, I MEASURED.
YEAH, IT'S 'CAUSE
THAT'S THE DISPENSING SPOON
THAT YOU HAVE.
IT'S NOT A MEASUREMENT.
I'M GONNA SIFT.
THAT'S YOUR FENCING MASK.
THAT'S NOT EVEN A REAL SIFT.
OH, WELL, HEY, YOU KNOW,
DO WHAT YOU GOT TO DO.
YOU CAN ALREADY SEE THE YEAST
STARTING TO DO
THE BUBBLE FEST IN THERE.
IS THIS HOW YOU MAKE ALL
YOUR PANCAKES? YOUR FLAPPERS?
YEP. YEP.
AND JUST LIKE
WITH ANY PANCAKE BATTER,
YOU DON'T WANT
TO MIX IT TOO MUCH.
IT'S OKAY TO HAVE
A FEW LUMPS.
YEP, LET THIS REST
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
CLEAN UP THE APPLE
FOR THE APPLE WALNUT SAUCE.
SO IN A SAUCEPAN, BROWN SUGAR,
HONEY AND MAPLE SYRUP MIX,
GRANNY SMITH APPLES,
WALNUTS.
WHAT A MIX.
CINNAMON-AMON-AMON.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS ALL MADE TO ORDER
EACH TIME.
SOMEONE ORDERS THIS,
AND IT'S THE WHOLE THING,
EVERY SINGLE TIME?
YEP, EVERY SINGLE TIME.
OKAY, SO WHILE THAT REDUCES,
WE THROW THE 'CAKES ON.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE WAIT ON THESE GUYS.
THROW IN A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM.
THAT'S LIKE
A CANDY APPLE GONE WILD.
PRETTY MUCH.
FLIP 'EM OVER. OKAY.
(whistles) THAT'S A STACK.
THAT MUCH GOES ON THERE?
YEP.
THROW IN A LITTLE BIT OF BRIE.
GOOD LUCK.
HOW DO YOU RECOMMEND
EATING THIS?
DON'T SAY "WITH A FORK."
TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
OH. DELICIOUS.
LOOK AT THE CAKE.
WHEN YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT A PANCAKE
THAT'S GOT THAT KIND OF
NOOK AND CRANNY,
THE EXPANSION FROM THE YEAST--
NOW YOU PUT THE COMPONENT
OF THE TARTNESS
OF THE GRANNY SMITH,
THE CRUNCH OF THE WALNUT.
YOU GET THE SYRUP
AND THE SWEETNESS,
BUT THEN YOU GET THE CREAMINESS
OF THE BRIE...
OF THE BRIE.
AND THE ACID OF THE BRIE
COMING IN. MMM.
WE SHOULD ALL KNOW THAT THIS IS
HOW IT'S SUPPOSED TO GO.
YOU JUST HAD TO BE
THE ONE TO TELL US.
APPLE WALNUT AND BRIE.
REALLY RICH, REALLY FLAVORFUL.
I'D RECOMMEND THIS FLAPPER
TO ANYBODY. IT'S FABULOUS.
WE'VE TRIED
PANCAKES EVERYWHERE,
BUT THE FLAPPERS HERE
ARE BY FAR THE BEST.
HERE YOU ARE.
WE COME HERE AS OFTEN
AS WE CAN.
MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
IT'S REALLY QUITE
A RESTAURANT.
UP IN TWO.
IT REALLY IS
A LITTLE NEIGHBORHOOD CAFE,
AND IT'S LIKE ONE BIG FAMILY.
(woman) AWESOME.
BESS SAYS SHE COULD NOT
BE HAPPIER.
HERE YOU GO. PLATE 'EM UP.
SHE HAD A VISION
AND MADE IT REAL...
COMING UP HERE.
WHICH MEANS FOR HER,
IT'S TIME TO MOVE ON.
LET'S GO ON
TO THE NEXT ADVENTURE.
I'M HEADED NEXT
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS.
GONNA OPEN UP A B AND B--
GATEWAY GUEST.
AND HER LITTLE
NEIGHBORHOOD CAFE...
ORDER UP.
CHEF ELIZABETH TINUCCI
IS TAKING OVER...
HOW DO YOU LIKE THE BRIE CUT?
AND SHE SAYS SHE'S GONNA KEEP
ALL THE COLOSSAL CLASSICS.
SHE'S GOT A REALLY GOOD THING
GOING RIGHT NOW.
I'M GONNA KEEP
ALL THE FAVORITES,
THE APPLE WALNUT BRIE,
SAVORY SCONES.
YOU DID IT.
I THINK IT'S TIME
FOR SOMEONE ELSE TO COME IN
AND BRING IT
A LITTLE FURTHER.
I'LL COME BACK AND VISIT.
NEXT STOP,
WE'RE HEADING TO NEW JERSEY...
J-BELL.
IT'S A UNIQUE PLACE TO EAT.
FOR DOGS...
THE SAUERKRAUT
HAS BEER IN IT.
YOU JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
STARTIN' THE SOPRANO DOG.
IT'S GOT SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY.
YOU KNOW, I LOVE
GETTING YOUR E-MAILS,
AND I GOT A WHOLE STACK
FROM THE FOLKS
ALL OVER THE EAST COAST
ABOUT A JOINT
ON THE JERSEY SHORE.
THEY WANT TO SHOW ME
THEIR FAVORITE HOT DOG STAND
IN NORTH WILDWOOD, NEW JERSEY,
AND HERE'S WHAT THEY'RE SAYING
ABOUT MAUI'S DOG HOUSE.
I E-MAILED YOU BECAUSE
THIS IS ONE OF THE FEW PLACES
IN NEW JERSEY
YOU CAN GET A REAL HOT DOG.
(man) CHICAGO.
MAUI'S IS THE MOST FUN PLACE
FOR A HOT DOG.
J-BELL.
IT'S A UNIQUE PLACE TO EAT.
WITH A UNIQUE WAY
OF DISHING IT UP.
117.
MAUI'S SERVES EVERYTHING
IN THESE DOG BOWLS,
HENCE, MAUI'S DOG HOUSE.
WHERE A GUY NAMED
MIKE DANTUONO A.K.A. MAUI...
NO GUTS, NO GLORY.
AND HIS WIFE LIZ...
(Liz) COMING UP.
ARE MAKING
THEIR OWN KIND OF DOGS.
WE HAVE TWO TYPES OF DOGS--
TRADITIONAL GERMAN FRANK--
BEEF, PORK, AND VEAL--
AND A WHITE FRANK,
WHICH IS VEAL AND PORK.
AND E-MAILERS
ARE GOING NUTS FOR 'EM.
GOURMET DOG
WITH GOURMET TOPPINGS.
SOPRANO.
PEOPLE COME HERE SPECIFICALLY
FOR THE TOPPINGS
BECAUSE THEY'RE SO UNIQUE.
DRESSED DOG.
FROM HOMEMADE BEEF SAUCE...
MIKE'S TEXAS SAUCE IS WONDERFUL.
TO DRUNKEN SAUERKRAUT...
THE SAUERKRAUT
HAS BEER IN IT.
TO A SPICY MUSTARD...
(Liz) HORSERADISH MUSTARD.
MADE IN-HOUSE.
EVERYTHING HERE IS FRESH,
HOMEMADE, MADE DAILY.
IT'S REALLY CRAZY BACK THERE.
(Maui) ORDER UP!
JUST RUNNING ALL AROUND,
COOKING ALL THE HOT DOGS.
LAST TIME I CHECKED,
I ONLY HAD TWO HANDS.
AND MAUI'S FANS KNOW
TO CALL THEIR DOGS BY NAME.
CAN I GET
A HORSEY IN CHICAGO?
HORSERADISH MUSTARD, RELISH,
ONIONS, PEPPERONCINI, TOMATOES.
CHICAGO DOG.
PERFECT COMBINATION.
IT IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
A DRUNKEN HORSE.
SPICY KICKED-UP MUSTARD,
THE SAUERKRAUT
IS COOKED IN BEER.
YOU CAN'T BEAT THE COMBINATION.
IT'S JUST GREAT.
STARTING THE SOPRANO DOG.
(man) BABY SPINACH,
LITTLE GARLIC.
IT'S GOT SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY.
BEACHCOMBER.
IT HAS COLESLAW AND RELISH
ON IT. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(Liz) ITALIAN DOG.
IT'S GOT PEPPERS, ONION,
POTATO, CHEESE--DELICIOUS.
IF SOMEBODY ASKED ME
WHAT WAS SO GREAT ABOUT MAUI'S,
I WOULD PROBABLY SAY
YOU'VE NEVER EATEN HERE.
OR HAD THE MAUI'S SPECIALTY
FOLKS CAN'T STOP TALKING ABOUT.
SALTY POTATO BALLS.
THESE ARE SALTY POTATO BALLS.
THEY SOAK 'EM IN BRINE.
THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
BOY, ARE THEY SALTY.
EVERY TIME I COME DOWN HERE,
I TRY TO GET THEM
BEFORE HE SELLS OUT OF THEM.
EVERYTHING HERE IS TOP-NOTCH.
EVERYTHING IS FRESH.
AND SO IS THE ATMOSPHERE.
WE HAVE TO BE
"POLITICALLY CORRECT" AGAIN?
THE OWNERS ARE GREAT. YOU KNOW,
LIZ AND MAUI ARE THEMSELVES.
THEY ARE FUNNY, SO WE COME
FOR A GOOD HOT DOGS AND A LAUGH.
CARDIAC ARREST. TELL ME IF
HE NEEDS TO GO TO THE HOSPITAL.
THEY MAKE FUN OF YOU,
AND I KNOW THAT'S PRETTY SICK,
BUT IT MAKES ME LAUGH.
MY PRINCESS.
DON'T LIE.
MAUI'S KNOWN FOR
SARCASM, GREAT FOOD.
(Liz) FUHGEDDABOUDIT.
IT'S ALWAYS
A REALLY GOOD HOT DOG.
(Maui) J-BELL.
AND THIS IS THE BEST.
THIS IS THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
'CAUSE I MADE IT.
JUST THE PERFECT SUMMER THING,
TO EAT A HOT DOG, SIT OUTSIDE,
AND YOU ENJOY SUMMER.
SALTY POTATO BALLS.
MAKE A POINT OF STOPPING
AT MAUI'S DOG HOUSE.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
AND WE MAKE BREAKFAST SANDWICHES
ON THEM, TOO.
AH!
THEY DIDN'T
JUST GET MEAT ON IT.
DON'T. DON'T. DON'T.
LIKE SAUSAGE.
(stuttering)
SAUSAGE. SAUSAGE ON THAT,
HEATED UP. COME ON.
OH.