HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE I'LL TRY IT. MMM.
SWEET...
WE MAKE CHOCOLATE CAKES. WE MAKE
FRUIT TARTS, CHEESECAKES.
AND SAVORY.
FRESH COUNTRY SAUSAGE.
YEAH.
MMM.
IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA...
REUBEN.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
WE COME HERE
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
CRANKIN' OUT
BISON POT ROAST...
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
AND BANANA CREAM PIE.
MMM.
THAT'S PRETTY DYNAMITE.
IN ARLINGTON, VIRGINIA...
PORK CHOP DINNER.
THE CLASSIC DINER...
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS A REAL DINER.
DOING ALL...
(woman) ENJOY.
THE DINER CLASSICS.
NICE GRAVY ON IT,
BIG PORTION. MMM.
AND IN
BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA...
FRESH, JUST MAGNIFICENT.
THE LOCAL JOINT.
EVERYTHING IS ALWAYS
PERFECTLY PREPARED.
PUTTIN' A SPIN
ON PULLED PORK...
PULLED PORK
IN A COCONUT CURRY.
AND EVEN APPLE PIE.
AND THEN I HIT THE GRAPES.
G-R-A-P-E? DUDE.
GRAPE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN DULUTH, MINNESOTA,
IN
THE LINCOLN PARK NEIGHBORHOOD.
NOW THIS USED TO BE CALLED
THE WEST END,
AND THIS IS WHERE
ALL THE WORKERS
FROM THE SHIPPING INDUSTRY
ON LAKE SUPERIOR USED TO LIVE.
IT'S NOW AN UP-AND-COMING AREA,
AND HOME TO A RESTAURANT VET
THAT LEFT THE CORPORATE WORLD
TO DO HIS OWN GIG.
THIS IS DULUTH GRILL.
FRESH HOMEMADE LOTSA'S UP.
MOST EVERYTHING
IS HOMEMADE HERE.
WALLEYE DINNER.
THAT LOCAL FLAVOR THAT WE ALL
LOVE HERE IN DULUTH.
WE WANTED IT TO BE
A HOMETOWN RESTAURANT.
B.L.T. IN THE WINDOW.
'CAUSE FOR OWNER
TOM HANSON...
REUBEN.
AFTER YEARS ON THE ROAD AS
A REGIONAL RESTAURANT MANAGER,
IT WAS TIME TO COME HOME.
BISON BURGER.
GOT TO DO SOMETHING WHERE
I CAN SEE MY KIDS GROW UP.
SHORT STACK
COMIN' AT YOU.
SO WHEN HE
AND HIS WIFE JAIMA...
LET'S GO.
SAW THIS LOCAL JOINT
FOR SALE...
WE MADE A FEW PHONE CALLS,
AND A MONTH LATER, WE WERE IN.
CRANKIN' OUT EVERYTHING
THE LOCALS LOVE...
FLIPPIN' BURGERS.
FROM STUFFED MEAT PIES
CALLED PASTIES...
PASTIE IN THE WINDOW.
A MINNESOTA STAPLE--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TO ALL KINDS
OF FRESH-BAKED PIES.
STRAWBERRY PIE
IN THE WINDOW.
I LOVE ALL THEIR PIES HERE,
BUT THEIR BANANA CREAM PIE
IS PERFECT.
AND IT'S
THEIR NUMBER ONE SELLER.
BANANA CREAM PIE IS UP.
THIS COULD NOT
HAVE COME OUT OF A BOX.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THAT CRUST?
IT'S GREAT.
THEY'RE ROCKIN' 'EM OUT.
YEP, THEY ARE.
THE CRUST IS...
THAT'S WHERE IT ALL BEGAN.
THAT'S WHERE IT ALL--
EGGS...
A LITTLE LIQUID CHICKEN.
WHITE VINEGAR,
GOT SOME ICE-COLD WATER,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA MIX HERE.
OKAY, SO THIS IS ALL SET.
WE'RE GONNA COME OVER HERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA START
ON THE PIECRUST
WITH THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
IN THIS BOWL APPARATUS?
WHY AREN'T WE DOING THIS
IN A MIXER?
THIS IS HOW--
IT'S HOW I WAS TAUGHT.
THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
WE GOTTA STIR THE SALT
IN HERE.
VEGETABLE SHORTENING.
YEP, AND THIS IS
BUTTER-FLAVORED SHORTENING.
SO I JUST SQUEEZE
THE SHORTENING
UNTIL SOME FLOUR STICKS
TO IT.
NEXT, WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE LIQUID.
CONTINUOUSLY FOLD UNTIL THIS
QUITS STICKING TO MY HANDS.
SO THERE'S OUR CRUST.
THIS IS GONNA
BE SUPER-FLAKY.
PLASTIC WRAP.
SO THIS GOES TO THE FRIDGE
TO COOL FOR A FEW HOURS,
AND THEN WE'LL ROLL IT OUT?
YEP, NOW WE'RE GONNA
ROLL OUT THE DOUGH.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU ROLL THIS OUT
EL PAPER-THIN-O.
YEAH.
THIS IS A 7-INCH PLATE.
RIGHT THERE
IN THE CENTER, HUH?
WE'RE JUST TAKING FOUR
OUT OF HERE.
OH.
THERE'S 12 LITTLE SLOTS
IN THE MUFFIN TIN,
BUT WE ONLY USE FOUR
AT A TIME.
SO YOU'RE GONNA PUT
THAT ENTIRE
ENORMOUS MUFFIN TIN IN
AND ONLY USE FOUR SLOTS?
THEN WE FORM 'EM.
PIERCE THE BOTTOM A LITTLE
SO IT DOESN'T PUFF UP,
AND THEN
A LITTLE EGG WASH.
I LIKE THIS.
AND THEN SUGAR.
AND WE'RE GONNA LET
THESE BLIND-BAKE?
YEP.
BLIND-BAKE--LET 'EM BAKE
WITHOUT PUTTING ANY FILLING
OR ANYTHING IN 'EM.
NOW THE PIE SHELLS
GO IN THE OVEN.
EIGHT TO TEN MINUTES,
AND WE'LL PULL 'EM OUT,
LET 'EM COOL, AND HIT 'EM
WITH THE CUSTARD?
YEP.
THE FILLING.
VANILLA CREAM PIE FILLING.
WE'RE GONNA ADD MILK
AND THEN SOME SUGAR.
ALL RIGHT,
CORNSTARCH, SALT.
THERE YOU GO.
BRING THIS
TO A QUICK BOIL HERE.
AND WE'RE GONNA
TEMPER THESE EGGS.
WHEN IT'S SUPERHOT,
IT WOULD JUST COOK THE EGGS
WHEN THEY DROP IN,
AND THEN WE WOULD HAVE
LIKE A SCRAMBLED EGG MIXTURE.
BUT ADDING A LITTLE BIT
OF LIQUID SLOWLY
WILL TEMPER THE EGGS, AND THEN
WE CAN ADD IT ALL BACK IN.
THIS GIVES US
THE NICE YELLOW COLOR.
ONCE IT COMES TO A BOIL,
WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD OUR VANILLA
AND LET OUR BUTTER
JUST MELT IN.
WE'LL LET THAT COOL DOWN, AND
IT'LL BE READY TO SERVE IT UP?
YEP.
GIDDYAP.
SLICE OUR BANANA WITH A DOLLOP
OF WHIPPED CREAM IN THE CENTER.
SO IT'LL STICK LIKE THIS.
LINE THE CRUST WITH BANANA.
PUT A NICE SCOOP
OF VANILLA PUDDING.
THAT'S A VERY NICE
PRESENTATION--LABOR-INTENSIVE.
YOU GOTTA DO
POWDERED SUGAR FIRST
SO THE CARAMEL SITS ON TOP,
AND THAT IS IT.
THEN YOU JUST HAVE TO BREAK IT
INTO PIECES
AND DESTROY IT.
OKAY.
THAT'S PRETTY DYNAMITE.
THE CRUST IS UP THERE WITH
"MADE BY SOME OF THE BEST."
SUPER-FLAKY, BUT IT'S GOT
SOME BODY TO IT.
THE VANILLA CREAM
IS NOT SUPERSWEET.
YOU KNOW WHAT THE KICKER IS?
THE EGG WASH.
AND THEN THAT SUGAR IS KIND OF
REMINISCENT OF A SUGAR COOKIE.
I DON'T THINK I COULD EAT
THE WHOLE THING.
I'M DOING A PRETTY GOOD JOB
OF IT, THOUGH. MMM!
(chuckles)
BANANA CREAM PIE IS UP.
LIGHT, FLAKY--
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
PIE FOR TABLE 54.
I'VE NEVER HAD
A BAD MEAL HERE.
WILD RICE MEATLOAF DINNER.
'CAUSE TOM'S ALL ABOUT GIVIN'
FOLKS WHAT THEY WANT.
THE BIG VEGGIE SALAD.
WE STARTED
MAKING VEGETARIAN,
AND THEN I HAD CUSTOMERS ASKING
ME IF I COULD DO GLUTEN-FREE.
GLUTEN-FREE TURKEY BURGER.
WE LIKE NEW THINGS.
WE LIKE ORGANIC.
BEAN & TEMPEH BURRITO
IS UP.
THEY GROW THEIR VEGETABLES
OUT IN THE PARKING LOT.
UP HERE IN DULUTH? I MEAN,
THIS IS MEAT AND POTATO COUNTRY.
PLATIN' UP
A POT ROAST DINNER.
OH, HE'S DOING THAT, TOO,
WITH A LOCAL TWIST.
GRASS-FED BISON.
IT'S DIFFERENT.
IT'S FLAVORFUL.
(Jaima)
DAKOTA POT ROAST.
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE DOING
OUR DAKOTA POT ROAST.
THIS IS OUR 20-POUND
BISON ROAST CHUCK.
THAT'S A CHUCK ROAST?
THAT IS A CHUCK.
SO LEAN, IT'S INCREDIBLE.
THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYIN'.
SO A CHUCK ROAST. CHECK.
START IT
WITH A SIMPLE RUB--
BLACK PEPPER,
CELERY SEED, SALT...
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GRANULATED GARLIC. I'M JUST
GONNA STIR THAT AROUND.
OKAY.
THAT NOW IS READY. JUST PUT
SOME MIREPOIX IN THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAN--CARROTS,
ONIONS, AND CELERY.
NOW WE'LL ADD THE BISON.
WE'RE GONNA PIERCE THE ROAST.
(humming "Psycho" music)
A LITTLE "PSYCHO"
INTO THIS.
NOW WE'LL ADD
SOME MINCED GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA GET THIS RUB
EVENLY SPREAD. IT'S NOT READY.
DO THE WANT THE REST
OF YOUR MIREPOIX?
YEP, I'M JUST GONNA
COVER THE TOP.
WE LET THIS MARINATE FOR ABOUT
FIVE HOURS TO OVERNIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD ABOUT 1/2 GALLON
OF WATER HERE.
JUST SO IT COVERS A LITTLE BIT
ON THE SIDES.
THEN WE'LL WRAP IT IN FOIL, AND
IT'S READY TO GO IN THE OVEN.
300, 325
FOR ABOUT 5 HOURS?
YEP.
IT SHOULD BE DONE. WE'LL TAKE
THE ROAST OUT OF THE PAN
AND STRAIN THE LIQUID
FOR THE GRAVY.
SO WE'VE STRAINED IT.
MAKIN' A REAL FAST
BLOND ROUX.
BUTTER, FLOUR--
EQUAL PARTS.
HE'S MAKING THE ROUX RIGHT NOW
AS A THICKENING AGENT, RIGHT?
ALL IT DOES
IS TIGHTEN OUR STOCK.
WELL, THAT'S GONNA MAKE
A MESS OF GRAVY.
A LITTLE KITCHEN BOUQUET,
NICE RICH COLOR.
THAT'S ACTUALLY LOOKIN'
REALLY GOOD.
(laughs)
THE BISON HAS JUST RESTED LONG
ENOUGH NOW FOR US TO CUT IT.
IT'S GOT
A CRISPY OUTSIDE CRUST,
NICE TENDER INSIDE.
IT JUST FALLS APART.
LOOK AT THAT FALL APART.
THAT GOES LIKE THAT
WITH THE VEGETABLES.
THE SUPER GRAVY.
I LIKE THE WAY YOU ROLL.
THAT IS COMFORT FOOD 101--
REALLY NICE TEXTURE,
NOT ONLY REALLY TENDER,
BUT IT HAS A REAL BEEF FLAVOR
FROM THE MEAT ITSELF,
AND THE GRAVY IS JUST ON POINT.
YOU HAVE A KNACK FOR PULLIN'
IT OFF AND MAKIN' IT TASTY.
DAKOTA POT ROAST.
FALLS APART IN YOUR MOUTH.
WILD RICE MELT.
THE BEST RESTAURANT
YOU'RE GONNA FIND IN DULUTH.
CHOCOLATE CAKE.
(woman) WE COME HERE
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
NO, YOU DON'T.
WE DO.
YES, WE DO. SHE'S GOT
THE CLEANEST OVEN IN TOWN.
I BET YOU SHE DOES.
UP NEXT...
(man) SHRIMP SANTORINI.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO VIRGINIA...
IT'S OUR GO-TO DINER.
FOR A REAL...
BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
HEAVY HITTER.
HOLY CHALLAH.
WE'RE HERE
IN ARLINGTON, VIRGINIA,
ABOUT 3 MILES OUTSIDE OF D.C.
TO VISIT THE KIND OF DINER
THE EAST COAST IS FAMOUS FOR.
I MEAN, TONS OF STAINLESS STEEL,
A HUGE MENU,
OPEN LATE NIGHT WITH A BAKERY
IN THE BASEMENT.
I MEAN, THIS IS
THE KIND OF DINER
DINER FANS ARE LOOKIN' FOR.
THIS IS METRO 29.
HERE'S YOUR GREEK OMELET.
IT'S OUR GO-TO DINER.
TABLE 48.
IT'S HOMEMADE AND FRESH.
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS A REAL DINER.
(man) SHRIMP SANTORINI.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE I'LL TRY IT.
MMM.
YOU CAN EAT HERE
FIVE DAYS A WEEK
AND HAVE SOMETHING DIFFERENT
EVERY DAY.
THANKS TO DINER VET
PETER BOTA.
I'M DOING WHAT I LOVE.
AND HE'S BEEN
DOING IT HERE...
TABLE 13.
FOR THE LAST 15 YEARS.
YOU BUILT THIS DINER
FROM SCRATCH GROUND UP.
HOW MANY SQUARE FEET?
6,000 ON 2 LEVELS,
SO 12,000 TOTAL.
TYPICAL MONSTER
DINER STYLE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LEMON CHICKEN.
WITH A TYPICAL
MONSTER DINER MENU.
"SHRIMP SANTORINI,
ROAST BEEF DINNER,
PORK CHOPS,
AND AN ORDER OF PANCAKES."
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
BREAKFAST--
OH, YOU'RE GONNA TAKE ME
THROUGH THE WHOLE MENU.
I'M GONNA TAKE YOU
GET ON, FOLKS.
IT'S FRENCH TOAST.
FOR LUNCH, THE GYRO SANDWICH,
AND DINNER,
I HAVE TO SAY LAMB.
THE TASTIEST LAMB
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
COOKED UP BY
LONGTIME HEAD CHEF...
LEG OF LAMB.
NICK ATHANASIOU.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
LEG OF LAMB WITH POTATOES.
BIG LEG.
THAT'S A BIG LEG.
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE THAT LITTLE BIT
OF FAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
SEE HOW NICE
AND PINK THE MEAT IS HERE?
AND THIS,
I'M GONNA CUT IT OFF.
PULLIN' THE SHANK OFF.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW I GOT IT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE BONE OUT?
YES.
THIS IS
A FULL-DEAL PROGRAM HERE.
YEAH.
AND WHY DON'T YOU BRING IT IN
WITH THE BONE ALREADY TAKEN OUT?
IT'S BETTER LIKE THIS.
LOOK AT THAT. WOW.
NICE JOB, BUDDY.
YEP. THANK YOU.
BY TYING THIS UP, WE BRING
ALL THAT MEAT TOGETHER
SO IT'S GOT A CHANCE
TO GO LOW AND SLOW,
AND THEN IT'S GONNA
BE NICE AND TENDER.
ALL RIGHT, DONE.
BONED...
BONED.
ROLLED, AND TIED--
B.R.T.
TIED. OKAY.
WE HAVE A FEW THINGS--
CARROTS,
CELERY, ONIONS...
YOU DO IT WITH SUCH GRACE.
(chuckles) GARLIC.
OKAY.
I PULLED THE BONES OUT--
FROM THE LAMB BEFORE.
THOSE ARE GONNA KEEP IT FROM
STICKING RIGHT ONTO THE BOTTOM?
THAT'S IT, YEAH.
PLUS, YOU GET THE MARROW OUT
OF THE BONES WHEN IT COOKS.
YEAH, RIGHT.
PUT A LITTLE SALT
ON THE BOTTOM, PEPPER,
AND OREGANO, A LITTLE BIT.
PUT THE LAMB HERE.
OKAY.
I PUT SALT, PEPPER, OREGANO.
PUT 'EM IN THE OVEN
FOR 50 MINUTES.
AND AFTER THAT,
I PUT WATER IN THERE.
BROWN IT OFF.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME MOISTURE TO IT.
AND LET 'EM COOK FOR ONE HOUR.
TURN 'EM OVER.
ONE MORE HOUR,
AND IT'S READY.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
SERVE IT WITH WHAT?
POTATOES.
IT'S DONE?
DONE.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND I PUT 'EM IN A POT.
I TAKE THE WATER, THE JUICE,
AND WE'RE GONNA USE
THAT FOR GRAVY.
YOU DON'T SEE IT EVERY DAY--
LAMB GRAVY.
WANT SOME HEAT
ON THAT, BOSS?
PUT THE HEAT ON IT, YEAH.
YOU'RE TAKIN' A LITTLE BIT
OF THE OIL OFF THE TOP
OF THE, UH, JUS.
I JUST PUT A DROP OF--
KITCHEN BOUQUET
FOR A LITTLE, UH, COLOR?
JUST FOR A LITTLE BROWNING.
CORNSTARCH SLURRY--GONNA TIGHTEN
UP THAT LAMB GRAVY.
WE'RE GOOD?
YEAH, THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH.
SLICE THE LAMB
AND SERVE IT UP?
AND SERVE IT UP.
AND THIS IS YOUR TRADITIONAL
GREEK SUNDAY, RIGHT?
SUNDAY...
AND THE POTATOES HAVE GARLIC
AND OREGANO.
GARLIC, OREGANO,
SALT AND PEPPER.
HE TRIMMED IT,
TOOK THE BONE OUT OF IT,
TIED IT UP,
AND HE ROASTED IT.
THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT
FOR A SUNDAY. MMM.
GOOD?
MMM, GOOD.
(chuckles)
BIG FLAVOR COMIN' OUT
OF THE BONES.
LOOK AT THAT, NICE GRAVY ON IT,
BIG PORTION.
MMM. SERIOUSLY GOOD.
THE LAMB BY ITSELF IS GREAT.
THE KICKER THERE IS THE GRAVY.
PAN JUICES REALLY JUST KIND OF
TIE IT ALL TOGETHER.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS FROM
THE VEGETABLES. MMM. NICE JOB.
THANKS.
LEG OF LAMB. ENJOY.
THIS IS SUNDAY DINNER
AT GRANDMOTHER'S HOUSE.
WHERE ELSE ARE YOU GONNA GET
LAMB GRAVY MADE FROM SCRATCH?
(speaking indistinctly)
IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
THAT'S WHAT I LOVE ABOUT IT.
IT'S SO FRESH,
AND IT TASTES SO GOOD.
HERE WE GO.
THE DESSERTS ARE GREAT.
WE MAKE CHOCOLATE CAKES.
WE MAKE FRUIT TARTS,
CHEESECAKES, CREAM PIES.
CHALLAH BREAD.
FOR A BREAKFAST FAN FAVORITE.
HERE'S YOUR FRENCH TOAST.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
THE CHALLAH BREAD
FOR FRENCH TOAST IS GOOD.
CHALLAH BREAD
FOR THE FRENCH TOAST?
YEAH. RIGHT.
MILK AND WATER, SALT.
HOW MANY LOAVES
IS THIS GONNA MAKE?
TEN LOAVES.
SUGAR, VEGETABLE OIL...
OKAY.
EGGS, AND YEAST.
THAT'S A LOT OF YEAST.
YEAH. FOOD COLOR.
A LITTLE EGG SHADE, GIVE IT
A NICE LITTLE YELLOW HUE.
A FEW MINUTES FOR EVERYTHING
TO MIX UP TOGETHER.
I LIKE THAT.
ALL RIGHT, I WANT TO PUT
THE FLOUR IN NOW.
HOW MANY ORDERS OF FRENCH TOAST
WILL ONE LOAF MAKE?
FIVE ORDERS.
IT HAS TO BEAT
LIKE TEN MINUTES.
HOW MANY ORDERS DO
YOU GO THROUGH A DAY?
IN A WEEKEND,
100 ORDERS.
THAT'LL MAKE YOU "CHALLAH."
(laughs)
WE READY?
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BENCH FLOUR.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
OKAY. THANK YOU.
GET AFTER THAT.
MAKE IT YOURS.
ALL RIGHT.
LIKE 3 1/2 POUNDS.
THAT IS CLOSE.
CLOSE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE MORE IS ALL RIGHT.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, PUT THEM DOWN.
I GOT LIKE THIS.
I TURN AROUND AGAIN.
GREASED-UP PAN.
HOW LONG
DO WE LET THESE PROOF?
ABOUT TWO AND HALF HOURS.
TWO AND A HALF HOURS,
THEN WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT
AT WHAT TEMPERATURE?
350.
FOR HOW LONG?
45 MINUTES.
WOW. HOLY CHALLAH.
READY? LISTEN.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
(thuds)
THAT'S HOW HEAVY THAT IS.
AND IT'S NOT HARD.
IT'S JUST THAT HEAVY,
THAT DENSE.
LET'S START COOKING.
ALL RIGHT.
MAKE THAT MIXED BATH.
SOME EGGS...
697...
VANILLA SYRUP,
THE SUGAR.
CINNAMON.
STIR THEM UP A LITTLE BIT
AND POUR IN MILK NOW.
AND IT'S READY.
HOW MANY PIECES
COME ON THIS?
TWO EACH ORDER.
GOOD? ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BUTTER IN IT.
SQUEEZE.
THIS IS THE DIET PORTION,
RIGHT?
DIET PORTION.
WHAT'S THIS
GONNA GET SERVED WITH?
SYRUP AND A LITTLE
CINNAMON ON TOP.
THAT'S HOT HOLY CHALLAH.
ALL RIGHT, CINNAMON
AND SYRUP.
MMM. COME ON.
IT'S DENSE. IT'S GOT A LITTLE
BIT OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
IT'S CREAMY, GREAT TEXTURE,
NICE CRUST ON THE OUTSIDE.
THAT'S THE WAY TO ROCK IT.
NICE JOB.
OKAY.
YOU GOTTA TRY THAT.
FRENCH TOAST.
FANTASTIC--
BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
(woman) IT'S JUST SO GOOD.
THE BREAD IS VERY DIFFERENT
FROM NORMAL FRENCH TOAST.
HOW WAS EVERYTHING?
EVERYTHING
IS JUST WONDERFUL.
MICKEY MOUSE PANCAKE.
THANK YOU.
I LOVE IT.
I EAT A LOT OF MEALS HERE.
PORK CHOP DINNER.
YOU GO OVER THE BRIDGE,
AND THE WHITE HOUSE
IS RIGHT THERE.
THE PRESIDENT SHOULD BE HERE.
HE'D HAVE A GOOD MEAL HERE, TOO.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
YOU GOT GREAT PEOPLE.
THIS IS THE REAL DINER FEEL,
SO CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADING
TO CALIFORNIA...
THIS IS MY FAVORITE RESTAURANT
IN THE UNIVERSE.
FOR APPLE PIE...
THE APPLE PIE IS GREAT.
MADE WITH GRAPES?
THE GRAPE APPLE PIE? DUDE.
GRAPE.
I'M ABOUT 1/2 MILE
OFF OF 580,
RIGHT ON THE BORDER OF BERKELEY
AND EMERYVILLE
HERE IN CALIFORNIA.
THIS AREA USED TO BE
PRIMARILY INDUSTRIAL.
NOW IT'S HOME TO A LOT
OF ARTISTS AND MUSICIANS
AND FUNKY LITTLE JOINTS
LIKE THIS ONE.
WELCOME TO MEAL TICKET.
EGG AND SAUSAGE BAGUETTE.
FAVORITE RESTAURANT
IN THE UNIVERSE.
(man) OOH, FANTASTIC.
BETTER THAN EVERY OTHER PLACE
I GO.
PICK UP.
FRESH EVERYTHING.
IT'S JUST MAGNIFICENT.
OKAY, THERE'S THAT ONE
DONE RIGHT.
JIMMY'S FOOD IS AMAZING.
SO IS HIS STORY.
YOU'RE AN OLYMPIC SWIMMER?
YEAH.
I SWAM FOR GREAT BRITAIN
IN THE OLYMPICS.
THEN TURNED TO COOKING
AFTER COLLEGE.
IT'S GOING DOWN.
AND 25 YEARS LATER,
JIMMY CARTER--
YEAH, THAT'S REALLY HIS NAME--
AND HIS WIFE
CAROLYN DEL GAUDIO...
WHERE'S THIS GOING NOW?
HAVE A PLACE OF THEIR OWN.
JIMMY JUST BRINGS
A FLAIR TO HIS COOKING.
LOVE THE DIFFERENT INFLUENCES
OF FOOD THAT COME INTO IT.
THAT ONE'S COMING ALONG.
YEP, THIS SCOTTISH-BORN CHEF'S
WHIPPING UP
A LITTLE AMERICAN SOUTHERN...
OYSTER PO'BOY
IS COMPLETELY DELICIOUS.
PLATING THE NOODLES.
A LITTLE THAI...
THE NOODLES ARE FANTASTIC.
EVEN THE TWO OF THEM
TOGETHER...
PULLED PORK
IN A COCONUT CURRY.
THIS IS NOT LIKE THE PULLED PORK
WE HAVE IN THE SOUTH.
WITH A LITTLE MEXICAN ADDED.
THEIR RICE AND SALSA
ARE AMAZING.
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
SLOW-ROASTED PORK
WITH A COCONUT CURRY SAUCE.
WITH TORTILLAS, SALSA,
'CAUSE YOU HAD SOME OF THIS
AND SOME OF THAT.
AND FLUNG IT TOGETHER.
SO FLING THIS TOGETHER.
I'M MAKING A RUB
WITH GARLIC POWDER,
ITALIAN SEASONING,
CHILI POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER--
FRESHLY GROUND...
ONLY WAY TO PLAY.
YEP, KOSHER SALT.
MIX THESE TOGETHER,
AND THEN WE RUB THE PORK
WITH IT.
BIT BONELESS PORK BUTTS.
YEP. 6 TO 8 HOURS
AT 350.
SO THESE ARE ROASTED OFF
AND COOLED.
THEN WE PULL IT APART.
(Austrian accent)
HE TORE IT RIGHT OFF.
(normal voice) SO THIS
ALL GETS SHREDDED UP?
GONNA MAKE
OUR SALSA FRESCA.
IT'S HARD WITH THE ACCENT.
I CAN SEE YOU SAYING,
"WE'LL MAKE SOME HAGGIS."
IT COMES OUT GOOD.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL TRUST YOU.
ORGANIC CHOPPED TOMATOES,
RED ONIONS, PASILLA PEPPERS.
AND SOME JALAPEÑO.
ROASTED, STEAMED,
AND CHOPPED UP.
FRESH CILANTRO,
OUR FRESH LIME JUICE...
TOASTED CUMIN.
KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
MIX IT UP.
I LIKE THIS SETUP.
NOW WE START GOING
ON THE CURRY SAUCE.
COCONUT MILK--PUT IT IN THERE--
KAFFIR LIME LEAVES,
HEAT UP THE PAN,
SESAME OIL..
GINGER.
GINGER, GARLIC--
THANK YOU.
AND THESE ARE CHINESE
BLACK BEANS FERMENTED.
AND WE GOT SOME THAI-STYLE
CURRY PASTE.
(whistles)
THANKS.
PUT THAT ALL IN THERE
TOGETHER.
SAUTé THAT DOWN, WE'LL MIX IT
INTO THE COCONUT MILK.
NOW?
PUT THE COCONUT CURRY SAUCE
INTO THE BIG POT, START PUTTING
THE PULLED PORK RIGHT IN.
JUST LET THIS SIT HERE
AND SIMMER FOR ABOUT...
AND HOUR AND A HALF,
TWO HOURS.
AND WE'RE READY.
I'M READY.
ALL RIGHT,
CILANTRO JALAPEÑO RICE,
COCONUT PIG, WE GOT
THE TORTILLAS,
OUR ALREADY-MADE SALSA,
AND THAT'S IT.
MMM.
YOU JUST CHANGED IT ALL.
ONE OF MY NEW FAVORITE WAYS
TO EATING PORK
IS NOW WITH COCONUT MILK,
KAFFIR LIME--MMM.
BUT THE SALSA IS WHAT
I WOULD NEVER HAVE EXPECTED.
NOT BAD FOR A SCOTTISH GUY.
PHENOMENAL.
(woman) SLOW-ROASTED PORK.
(woman) LIGHT, FRESH,
SPICY CURRY SAUCE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
IT'S SO TENDER.
IT'S A GREAT COMBINATION.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
IT'S ROCKIN'.
WHICH MAKES IT
THE KIND OF THING
YOU GOTTA SHARE
WITH ONE OF YOUR BROS.
NOW THIS... (laughs)
HE JUST REVEALED IT,
MY BROTHER FROM ANOTHER MOTHER--
STEVE FROM SMASH MOUTH.
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK,
BROTHER.
I LIKE THE LITTLE
CURRY TASTE IN THAT.
YOU GET THE CURRY,
THE COCONUT.
AND THAT CILANTRO--
REALLY GOOD.
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR IT
ALL DAY.
EVERYTHING I'VE EVER HAD HERE
HAS BEEN WONDERFUL.
DOING OKAY HERE.
WE TEND TO COME HERE
FOR BREAKFAST.
FROM SCRAMBLED EGGS
TO CORNMEAL PANCAKES...
FANTASTIC--MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
AND THIS FAN FAVORITE.
THE DOWN-HOME
COUNTRY SAUSAGE.
IT LOOKS HOMEMADE.
IT TASTES HOMEMADE.
'CAUSE IT IS HOMEMADE
FROM JIMMY'S OWN RECIPE.
MMM.
WE'RE ONTO THE WET MIX
FOR THE SAUSAGE.
THE WET MIX?
THAT BASICALLY BINDS
THE SAUSAGE TOGETHER.
WE'VE GOT EGGS, HALF-AND-HALF--
EXACT MEASUREMENTS.
YEAH, I LIKE
THE REAL PRECISE--ALLSPICE.
AND TOASTED FENNEL,
CUMIN, AND CORIANDER.
AND THAT RELEASES
THE FLAVOR.
WHISK ALL THESE TOGETHER.
KOSHER SALT,
BLACK GROUND PEPPER.
WHOA!
READY TO GO.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
CUT UP PORK BACK FAT,
FLING IT IN THE BOWL,
AND THEN WE GO
AT THE PORK BUTT.
CHICKEN BREAST--THAT'S ALL
GOING IN THE SAUSAGE--
OINK, OINK, CLUCK?
ABSOLUTELY.
INTO THE GRINDER. JUST MIX THEM
ALL THROUGH LIKE THIS.
FRESH CILANTRO IN THERE,
THE STALK AND ALL.
LOT OF FLAVOR IN THAT.
WHOLE JALAPEÑOS.
GARLIC IN THERE.
AND ONCE WE'VE GOT THAT,
THE WET MIX WE'LL ADD TO IT.
WE'LL MIX IT THOROUGHLY.
I LOVE THE WET MIX IDEA.
AND WE'LL JUST MAKE
SOME HANDMADE PATTIES.
OKAY, SO WE BUST THESE OUT.
FLING IT IN THE OVEN--20,
25 MINUTES IN A 350.
SO WHERE ARE WE AT,
BROTHER?
WE'LL DO SOME POTATOES.
PAR-BOILED, FINISH THEM OFF
ON TOP OF THE GRIDDLE--
SALT, PEPPER,
CRACK THE EGG.
THEN PULL THESE SAUSAGE.
THREE TO AN ORDER.
FINISH THEM OFF IN THE OVEN.
BREAD--HEAT THAT UP.
I FLIP THE EGG
A LITTLE BIT THERE.
I'M READY TO GO.
THE EGGS ARE RIGHT HERE.
POTATOES ARE OVER HERE. WE GET
OUR SAUSAGE--BOOM, BOOM, BOOM.
AND THEN WE PUT
THE BAGUETTE ON--READY TO GO.
MMM.
GREAT SAUSAGE. FLAVORFUL--
IT'S NOT ALL PORK.
YOU GET THE CHICKEN
IN THERE.
REMINDS ME OF SAUSAGE
WHEN I LIVED IN FRANCE.
FRESH COUNTRY SAUSAGE.
YEAH.
MMM, REALLY NICE.
PEOPLE MUST GO NUTS FOR THAT.
YEAH, THEY DO.
(woman) SAUSAGE AND EGGS.
DELICIOUS, FLAVORFUL,
AND LEAN.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
COMING RIGHT UP.
EVERYTHING IS ALWAYS
PERFECTLY PREPARED.
READY TO PICK UP.
JIMMY ALWAYS IS THROWING IN
SOMETHING LITTLE EXTRA.
CUTTING THE PIE.
EVEN WITH AN AMERICAN CLASSIC.
THE APPLE PIE IS GREAT.
AND THEN I HIT THE GRAPES.
G-R-A-P-E?
GRAPE.
TASTES LIKE HEAVEN.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
DUDE.
I GOT IT.
AT MEAL TICKET
IN BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA...
OKAY.
OWNER CAROLYN DEL GAUDIO
IS SERVING UP HER HUSBAND
JIMMY CARTER'S TAKE
ON SCRATCH-MADE FAVORITES.
OKAY, PLATING
THAI STYLE NOODLES.
JIMMY HAS A MAGIC TOUCH.
I GOT IT, YEAH.
HE JUST ADDS THAT
LITTLE EXTRA PUNCH OF FLAVOR
TO EVERYTHING THAT HE DOES.
JIMMY ALWAYS IS THROWING IN
SOMETHING LITTLE EXTRA,
SOMETHING THAT I THINK
I KNOW WHAT IT IS,
AND THEN I HIT THE GRAPES--
WOW.
THAT'S RIGHT--GRAPES
IN A SCRATCH-MADE APPLE PIE.
TASTES LIKE HEAVEN.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO, BROTHER?
THE DOUGH
FOR THE APPLE GRAPE PIE.
THE GREAT APPLE PIE?
IT TASTES GREAT.
IT'S GREAT?
BUT IT'S GRAPE.
G-R-A-P-E?
GRAPE.
IT'S A GREAT
GRAPE APPLE PIE.
GREAT--GREAT GRAPE
APPLE PIE?
YEP.
THAT'S WHAT THE NAME SHOULD BE--
GREAT GRAPE APPLE PIE.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
BUTTER CHOPPED UP.
THIS IS GONNA MAKE IT
SO IT'S NICE AND FLAKY.
YEP.
FLOUR, SUGAR,
SOME VANILLA.
CINNAMON.
THEN WE GET 'EM INCORPORATED
A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF HALF-AND-HALF IN THERE.
THEN YOU
JUST PULL IT ON OUT.
DO THAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
FAST, QUICK, AND EASY DOUGH.
YEP. PUT IT
IN THE PLASTIC WRAP.
REFRIGERATE IT
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
LET IT REST.
UNWRAP THIS.
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
AND THEN
I JUST PRESS IT OUT.
THEN WE GET
THE OLD ALUMINUM FOIL.
WE USE ALUMINUM FOIL HERE.
BY PUTTING THE BEANS ON IT
WITH THE FOIL,
IT'S GONNA KEEP FROM
BUBBLING UP AND PUFFING UP.
AND ALSO FALLING DOWN
THE SIDE.
BUT YOU DON'T WANT TO USE
THE BEANS AGAIN.
PUT THAT IN,
BAKE IT OFF.
45 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE READY TO GO
ON THE FILLING
FOR THE GREAT GRAPE APPLE PIE.
THE GREAT GRAPE APPLE PIE.
DICE SOME APPLES,
AND THEN I JUST CUT GRAPES
IN HALF.
GOT IT.
HEAT UP THE PAN.
GET SOME BUTTER.
TECHNICAL FORM
OF RIPPING IT WITH YOUR PAW.
YEAH.
PUT IN
THE APPLE-GRAPE MIXTURE,
SOME SUGAR, CINNAMON,
A SPLASH OF VANILLA.
PRECISE MEASUREMENTS AGAIN.
EXACTLY.
(clicks tongue) LET THIS COOK
DOWN TO SOFTEN EVERYBODY UP.
THERE'S THE CRUST. OKAY.
SO NOW...
FILL THAT UP
WITH THE MIXTURE.
TOP IT
WITH MY LITTLE TOPPING--
BUTTER, FLOUR, SUGAR,
CINNAMON, AND VANILLA.
THIS WILL MAKE
THE NICE LITTLE CRUST ON TOP.
AND THEN 350, MAYBE AN HOUR,
45 MINUTES.
THAT'LL TAKE AN HOUR
AND 45 MINUTES, REALLY?
IT TAKES A WHILE, YEAH.
ARE YOU READY?
THE PIE OUT OF THE OVEN.
WATCH OUT. IT'S HOT.
DON'T DO THIS AT HOME.
YOU'LL BURN YOUR LITTLE FINGERS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M TAKING THE PIE RIM
OFF OF HERE.
OH, NICE! LOOK AT THAT. SEE?
THAT REDEFINES KITCHEN BLING.
AND THEN GO AHEAD
AND CUT IT,
SERVE IT ON A PLATE
WITH HOMEMADE WHIPPED CREAM
WITH A BIT OF CARDAMOM
AND VANILLA.
DUDE. IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE CRUST IS NICE AND LIGHT.
APPLES KIND OF ROUND OUT
A LITTLE BIT,
TAKE ON THE CINNAMON
REAL WELL.
THE FLAVOR OF THE GRAPE...
OPENS UP THE PROFILE--
THE EFFERVESCENCE, YOU KNOW,
KIND OF THE SHARPNESS
OF THE GRAPE.
IT'S GOT
A LOT OF GREAT FLAVOR.
AND THEN TO TIE IT ALL ON TOP,
IT'S A CROSS BETWEEN
THE LIGHTEST MELTED ICE CREAM
THAT YOU'VE EVER HAD
AND WHIPPED CREAM.
DUDE, YOU ROCK IT OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
OUR APPLE GRAPE PIE.
IT'S APPLE-Y.
IT'S GRAPY.
THE CRUST IS CRUNCHY.
EXCUSE ME
WHILE I TAKE ANOTHER BITE.
PICKING UP.
IT'S VERY FRESH,
IT'S GORGEOUS TO LOOK AT,
AND IT'S EVEN BETTER
TO EAT.
JIMMY, WITH FOOD THAT GOOD,
YOU SHOULD RUN
FOR PRESIDENT.
(whispers) JIMMY CARTER.
(normal voice)
AWESOME JOB.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO HERE WE ARE 1/2 MILE
OFF 580
JUST SOUTH
OF BERKELEY, CALIFORNIA,
AND WE... (laughs)
(Guy) ROAD HOG!
LIES A LITTLE PLACE
CALLED MEAL TICKET.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
(laughs)