HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
EVERYTHING'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT HERE.
A LITTLE TWISTED.
WE GOT SOME APPLE WOOD CHIPS
AND COFFEE BEANS
TO ADD A MOCHA FLAVOR
TO IT.
IN MERRICK, NEW YORK.
TERIYAKI SALMON SALAD
READY TO GO.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
HIGH-END FOOD
AT A FAST-FOOD PRICE.
SCRATCH COOKING IT ALL...
ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
FROM SERIOUS SANDWICHES...
STEAK PANINI ON THE PRESS.
TO SPAGHETTI SQUASH.
MMM. NICE JOB.
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA.
...COMING BACK AND BACK.
I LOVE IT VERY MUCH.
THE JAPANESE
JOINT-TURNED DINER...
FIRE BURGER UP.
DOING A LITTLE BIT
OF THE OLD WORLD...
(man)
GERMAN BEEF ROULADEN IS UP.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF NEW.
BEET SLIDERS, TABLE 13.
FANTASTIC.
THIS GUY'S A GENIUS.
AND IN SUPERIOR, WISCONSIN.
MUSHROOM AND SWISS.
THE DIVE BAR...
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
DOING BURGERS...
THE MEAT IS AS FRESH AS CAN BE.
TRIPLE "D" VIEWERS...
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
YOU GOT TO COME CHECK
THIS PLACE OUT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ONE OF THE THINGS WE SAY
ON TRIPLE "D" IS SLOW DOWN,
TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
ANOTHER THING WE SHOULD SAY IS
DON'T JUDGE A BOOK BY ITS COVER,
LIKE THIS JOINT HERE
IN MERRICK, NEW YORK,
ON LONG ISLAND, ABOUT 35 MINUTES
OUTSIDE OF MANHATTAN.
MAY LOOK LIKE A FAST-FOOD BURGER
JOINT, BUT FROM WHAT I HEAR,
THE MENU INSIDE IS ALL ABOUT
REAL DEAL AND HOMEMADE.
WELCOME TO THE PIT STOP.
STEAK PANINI
IN THE WINDOW.
HIGH-END FOOD
AT A FAST-FOOD PRICE.
TERIYAKI SALMON SALAD
READY TO GO.
AMAZING ASIAN FLAVORS.
DRIBBLE DOWN
YOUR CHIN YUM.
EGGPLANT ROLLATINI.
REALLY GOOD ITALIAN FOOD.
ALL FROM HIGH-END ITALIAN CHEF
TONY RUBANO.
LITTLE FRESH MOZZARELL.
WHERE DID YOU GET YOUR
BACKGROUND ON FOOD?
GROWING UP IN AN ITALIAN HOUSE
IN BROOKLYN.
THEN WORKING JOINTS
ALL ACROSS MANHATTAN...
STEAK HOUSES,
LOBSTER HOUSES.
BEFORE BRINGING
HIS OWN SCRATCH-MADE MENU...
SPAGHETTI SQUASH WORKING.
TO LONG ISLAND...
EVERYTHING'S MADE TO ORDER.
FROM PASTA...
PENNE VODKA.
TO SALAD...
GRILLED SHRIMP
AND SCALLOP SALAD.
AND SERIOUS SANDWICHES.
PICKING UP
A CUBAN SANDWICH.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE WE
MAKING, BROTHER?
GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE PORK SHOULDER.
SEAR IT OFF
FOR A HOT CUBAN SANDWICH.
OKAY.
GET IT NICE AND CRISPY, AND THEN
OIL THE TOP OF THE PORK,
SALT AND THEN
A LITTLE PEPPER.
SO YOU GOT FAT, SKIN,
PORK, BONE.
YEAH. WE'RE GONNA SEAR IT
ON AS MANY SIDES AS WE CAN...
OKAY.
MAYBE 15, 20 MINUTES.
PORK-A-PUCK, GET A FRIEND.
BUY YOURSELF
A GIGANTIC FLAT... OH.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA GET IT
INTO THE STOCK POT.
ALL RIGHT.
DO THE VOODOO
THAT YOU DO.
A LITTLE OIL
IN A HEATED POT.
CHOPPED ONIONS ARE POPPED IN
THERE AND THEN CHOPPED CELERY.
OKAY.
CHOPPED CARROTS
TO FINISH UP HERE.
AND WE'LL LET THESE COOK DOWN
FOR ABOUT 10 OR 15 MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA GO
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK?
MAKE OUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK.
MAKE EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH?
FROM SCRATCH.
SERIOUSLY?
SWEAR. AND THEN
THE CRUSHED TOMATOES.
I'M GONNA SCOOP THIS
OFF THE GRILL
AND POP 'EM
RIGHT INTO THE STOCK POT.
HOW MANY OF THOSE
DO YOU MAKE A WEEK?
ABOUT HALF A DOZEN
TO EIGHT.
REALLY?
OH, SURE, SURE, SURE.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THE SAUCE, SAUCE, SAUCE?
NOW IT'S BOILED
FOR AN HOUR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THE PORK
SHOULDER AND STOCK IN THE OVEN
SIX OR SEVEN HOURS. NOW WE'RE
GONNA TAKE IT OUT OF THE OVEN.
OKAY.
LET IT COOL
THAT YOU CAN TOUCH IT.
BONE WANTS TO COME OUT.
THEN WE JUST START
TO BREAK IT DOWN.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR,
NICE BIG STRANDS.
DON'T NEED TO DO IT. I FEEL
I HAVE TO DO IT FOR YOU.
AND YOU WOULD LIKE THAT.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THIS SHREDDED PORK.
I'M GONNA POP IT
ON THE FLAT-TOP GRIDDLE,
CRISP IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
I LIKE IT, YEAH.
I'M GRAB THIS PANINI.
WE'RE GONNA CUT 'EM IN HALF,
AND WE'RE GONNA TOP THIS WITH
A LITTLE HOMEMADE HONEY MUSTARD
AND THEN FILL THIS SANDWICH
WITH SOME FIRE-ROASTED PEPPERS.
YOU ROAST THOSE YOURSELVES?
WE ROAST THESE.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
PICKLES. I'M GONNA GRAB MY PORK,
NICE LONG SHREDS IN THERE.
HOW BIG IS THIS SANDWICH?
IT'S HUGE.
GONNA PUT SOME TURKEY.
I'VE NEVER SEEN TURKEY
ON A CUBAN.
WHICH CUBANS HAVE YOU BEEN
HANGING OUT WITH?
UM, I DON'T KNOW.
PUT SOME VIRGINIA HAM.
IT'S REALLY THIS BIG?
EVERY DAY.
EVERYTHING WE DO IS BIG.
IT'S THE BIG APPLE.
THEN WE GOT SOME SWISS.
IF YOU PUT ANYTHING ELSE ON,
BESIDES THE BREAD TOP,
I'M LEAVING.
I THINK WE'RE GOOD. WE'RE GONNA
POP IT IN THE PANINI PRESS.
OKAY. HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA STAY IN THERE?
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
LET'S OPEN HER UP, PULL IT OUT.
WE'LL GIVE IT A CUT.
THEN WE'LL POP IT
ON THE PLATE HERE.
(imitating announcer)
HOME OF THE 6-POUND SANDWICH.
COME ON DOWN TO PIT STOP.
(normal voice) MMM.
PORK'S DYNAMITE.
THE HONEY DIJON ROCKS.
LOVE ANYTHING THAT'S GOT
RED BELL PEPPER IN IT,
GOOD VINEGAR
FROM THE PICKLE.
BUT THE BIG CALCULATION THAT
MAKES THIS ALL TIE TOGETHER,
THE BREAD
IN THE PANINI MAKER.
THAT'S REALLY THE KICKER HERE.
I MEAN, THAT IS NICE, CRUNCHY.
I MEAN, IT'S DONE RIGHT.
EVERYTHING'S MELTED
IN THE CENTER OF IT.
I MIGHT RECOMMEND YOU HAVE
A GOOD DENTAL PLAN.
TASTY SANDWICH.
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU, SIR.
OKAY, HOT CUBAN.
IT KIND OF ADDRESSES ALL
OF YOUR TASTE BUD SENSATIONS.
PORK IS VERY GOOD.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
IT'S HARD TO FIND
A CUBAN ANYWHERE
THAT TASTES LIKE SOMETHING
YOU GET DOWN IN MIAMI.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
I DIDN'T LIKE.
REALLY?
GOT A TUSCAN ROMAINE
PASTA SALAD.
PLENTY OF UPSCALE MEALS
THAT YOU WOULDN'T THINK
YOU WOULD FIND HERE.
THE NAME AND THE APPEARANCE
FROM THE OUTSIDE,
COMPLETE CONTRADICTION FROM
WHAT'S GOING ON IN THE INSIDE.
SALMON TERIYAKI DUXELLES.
IT STARTED OFF
AS A GREASY AND EASY
WITH CHICKEN FINGERS
AND WINGS AND FRIES.
BUT REAL QUICK,
FOLKS STARTED ASKING FOR MORE.
OUR CUSTOMERS SAY, "HEY, WHEN
YOU GONNA THROW SOME WRAPS ON?"
GOT A BARBECUE PORK WRAP,
YELLOW RICE.
THE WRAPS
ARE REALLY GOOD HERE.
AND HOW ABOUT SOME
OF YOUR SALADS?
TERIYAKI SALMON SALAD
READY TO GO.
TONY KNOWS WHAT I LIKE.
SHRIMP UP
FOR THE MECHANICS.
THEY REMEMBER YOU.
I JUST LOVE HAVING
A WELCOMING ENVIRONMENT.
HOW ARE YOU?
THEY MAKE YOU FEEL
LIKE FAMILY.
'CAUSE THIS JOINT IS FAMILY.
IS THAT THE BOYS'?
YEAH, THAT'S THE BOYS'.
YOUR WIFE WORKS WITH YOU.
GRILLED CHICKEN CAESAR
FOR YOU.
AND YOUR SON'S
ONE OF YOUR CHEFS.
YEAH, BRAD.
STEAK PANINI ON THE PRESS.
AND THEY'RE ALL CRANKING OUT
FAMILY RECIPES.
PENNE VODKA.
LIKE THIS FAN FAVORITE...
SPAGHETTI SQUASH.
TOPPED WITH TONY'S MOM'S
RED SAUCE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
GONNA MAKE A LITTLE MARINARA
SAUCE FOR OUR SPAGHETTI SQUASH.
FIRE IT UP.
HEAT UP THE SAUCEPAN.
POP IN A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
CHOPPED ONIONS,
SOME CHOPPED GARLIC.
JUST WANT IT TO BROWN UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
LITTLE PEPPER,
A LITTLE SALT.
THIS WAS THE RECIPE
THAT YOUR MOM TAUGHT YOU.
THIS IS WHAT WE DID
EVERY SUNDAY IN OUR HOUSE.
ADD SOME FRESH CRUSHED
ITALIAN TOMATOES.
SAN MARZANO?
YES, SIR.
SO THIS HAS HAD A CHANCE
TO SIMMER. NOW WHAT?
SOME REALLY GOOD PARMESAN.
RIGHT IN THE SAUCE NOW?
RIGHT IN THE SAUCE NOW, AND I'M
GONNA ADD A LITTLE FRESH BASIL.
WE ADD A LITTLE CHIANTI.
THAT'S REALLY A LITTLE.
AND THEN I'M GONNA JUST SIMMER
THIS AND CONTINUE TO STIR.
ALL RIGHT, SO...
NOW LET'S CUT
THE SPAGHETTI SQUASH.
FANTASTIC.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE GONNA BOIL
THESE, NOT ROAST 'EM.
IT'S JUST
A DIFFERENT FLAVOR.
OKAY.
THESE WILL COOK
FOR 10 TO 15 MINUTES.
NOW THE SPAGHETTI SQUASH
IS DONE.
SO WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO NOW?
I'M GONNA SPOON OUT THE SEEDS
AND FORK OUT THE FLESH.
AND WE'LL SAVE THE SHELLS
TO STUFF LATER.
WHAT ARE YOU INTO NOW?
WE'FOR THE SPAGHETTI SQUASH.ES
GIVE ME THE LOWDOWN
ON THE SHOWDOWN.
JUST HEAT UP THE PAN
WITH SOME OLIVE OIL,
SOME CHOPPED SHALLOTS,
SOME CHOPPED GARLIC.
OKAY.
SOME ONIONS, CHOPPED CARROT,
SOME CHOPPED CELERY,
RED BELL PEPPER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA SWEAT
ALL THE VEGGIES.
SWEAT 'EM DOWN.
SO YOU WANT TO HAVE
A LITTLE TEXTURE TO 'EM,
BUT YOU DON'T WANT 'EM
TO BE ALL THE WAY MUSHY.
YEAH, CERTAINLY NOT.
YELLOW SQUASH,
ZUCCHINI SQUASH.
UNCOOKED BROCCOLI
AND A LITTLE UNCOOKED ASPARAGUS.
(whistles)
AND THEN SOME PEPPER AND SALT,
A QUICK STIR.
THEN I'M GONNA ADD SOME MARINARA
SAUCE FOR A LITTLE COLOR
'CAUSE IT'S GONNA GET A BIT MORE
LATER IN THE PREPARATION.
YOU ACTUALLY KNOW
HOW TO COOK.
YOU'RE JUST NOT ANOTHER
PRETTY FACE.
(laughs) SO THAT'S THAT.
GONNA TAKE THE SQUASH AND JUST
POP SOME OF THIS IN HERE.
AND GIVE IT ANOTHER STIR
AND THEN SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA COOL IT
REAL QUICK.
ONE OF THESE
IS AN ORDER?
ONE OF THOSE
IS AN ORDER.
THAT'S GOT TO BE
8 OUNCES.
TOO BIG FOR YOU?
I'M NOT GONNA ANSWER THAT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE FRESH
TARRAGON IN THERE,
LITTLE MORE MARINARA,
AND NOW WE GIVE IT A TOSS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GRAB
A LITTLE BIT OF STUFFING
AND POP IT INTO THE SHELL.
WHOA, SOME BOUNTY
RIGHT THERE, HUH?
IT'S A GOOD LUNCH. THEN WE'LL
TOP WITH FRESH MOZZARELL.
IN THE OVEN FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
YOU'LL SEE THAT CHEESE START
TO BUBBLE UP A LITTLE BIT.
DIG IT.
GOOD. AND READY TO GO, A LITTLE
MARINARA ON THE PLATE.
(whistles)
LOOKS LIKE A PTERODACTYL LEG.
(imitates bird)
GIVE IT A LITTLE MORE SAUCE
ON THE TOP.
OKAY.
MMM. I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING
RIGHT NOW, BROTHER.
THAT MARINARA
IS RIGHT ON POINT.
MMM. LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE
THAT'S GENERATED
RIGHT DOWN IN THE BOTTOM OF THAT
FROM THOSE VEGGIES.
MMM. LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS,
SALTINESS OF THE MOZZ.
MMM. THE TIME,
THE DETAIL,
THE ENERGY, AND THE
APPRECIATION FOR FOOD--
NICE JOB.
YEAH, MAN.
SPAGHETTI SQUASH FOR YOU.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THAT WAS TASTY, HUH?
IT'S LIKE EATING SPAGHETTI
EVEN THOUGH IT'S A SQUASH.
I'M PICKING UP
A SPAGHETTI SQUASH.
THE MARINARA IS FANTASTIC.
THE VEGETABLES ARE FRESH
AND CRUNCHY.
OF COURSE, MELTED MOZZARELLA,
'CAUSE YOU CAN'T HAVE ANYTHING
WITHOUT MELTED MOZZARELLA.
THE FOOD
IS ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
I'VE GOT A LASAGNA HERE.
IT'S NICE TO BE ABLE
TO WALK INTO A PLACE,
AND THEY RECOGNIZE YOU,
AND THEY SHAKE YOUR HAND.
GOT A LITTLE
EGGPLANT ROLLATINI.
I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA
BE GOOD FOOD.
I JUST DIDN'T KNOW THAT IT
WAS GONNA BE GREAT FOOD.
THANKS. GLAD YOU ENJOYED.
UP NEXT...
ORDER UP.
WE'RE HEADING TO CALIFORNIA...
I LOVE COMING TO GATSBY'S.
FOR BEEF...
ROULADEN IS UP.
AND BEETS.
MMM. THAT'S OFF
THE BEATEN PATH.
HERE I AM
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA,
JUST A FEW BLOCKS FROM ONE OF
MY RESTAURANTS, TEX WASABI'S,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT'S
DOING TRADITIONAL EUROPEAN
AND UNIQUE VEGETARIAN.
I KNOW, WHAT A COMBO.
THIS IS GATSBY'S DINER.
BEET SLIDERS, TABLE 13.
IT USED TO BE
A JAPANESE RESTAURANT...
ITALIAN EGGPLANT, TABLE SIX.
WITH THE TEPPANYAKI GRILLS
OUT IN THE OPEN.
YOU'RE EXPECTING ASIAN CUISINE,
BUT YOU GET TO WATCH YOUR BURGER
GET COOKED.
ORDER UP,
BACON MUSHROOM SWISS.
I LOVE COMING TO GATSBY'S.
WE FELL
IN LOVE INSTANTLY.
(speaking German)
OR PORK LOIN.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
THEIR ITALIAN EGGPLANT BURGER
IS THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S ABOUT BOTH ENDS
OF THE SPECTRUM COMPLETELY.
KIND OF LIKE OWNERS
CHUCK CAPLENER...
MY MOM IS FROM GERMANY.
AND JERAD NUTTAL.
I'M FROM NORTH CAROLINA
ORIGINALLY.
A COUPLE OF SELF-TAUGHT CHEFS
WHO BROUGHT THEIR ROOTS...
PURPLE CABBAGE.
WITH THEM.
MY INFLUENCE
IS THE SOUTHERN
AMERICAN CUISINE,
AND HE BRINGS THAT
OLD-WORLD EUROPEAN STYLE.
AND TOGETHER, THEY'RE COMING UP
WITH THEIR OWN STYLE.
I HAD THE BEET SLIDERS.
NICE SLICE OF BEET THERE,
VERY RED.
THIS WILL GIVE YOU A NEW OUTLOOK
ON WHAT A BEET TASTES LIKE.
AND IT STARTS
WITH THEIR HOMEMADE DRESSING.
WHAT ARE WE
MAKING, BROTHER?
WE'RE MAKING SOME GREEN GODDESS
DRESSING FOR THE BEET SLIDERS.
FIRST, WE GOT A LITTLE CHOPPED
GREEN ONION, SOME TARRAGON,
LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY,
LEMON JUICE.
GOT TO HAVE THAT ACID
FOR MACERATION.
OKAY.
SOME BUTTERMILK,
AND WE PURéE THAT UP.
IT TURNS NICE AND GREEN, ADD
A BIT OF OUR HOUSE-MADE MAYO.
YOU MAKE THAT YOURSELF?
YES, SIR.
THAT VOLUME OF IT?
ACTUALLY, WE MAKE
WAY MORE THAN THIS.
WE MAKE ABOUT
5-GALLON BATCHES AT A TIME.
WOW.
YEAH.
IMPRESSED.
SOUR CREAM.
NOW DID YOU MILK THE COW
FOR THIS?
ADD THE COLOR TO OUR
GREEN GODDESS DRESSING.
WE GIVE IT A NICE STIR.
HOW LONG WE GONNA LET THAT
SET UP FOR?
15 OR 20 MINUTES.
LOOKS GOOD.
THIS IS GOING
ON THE BEET SLIDERS.
IT IS.
ALL RIGHT. YOU GUYS READY
FOR THIS? BEET SLIDERS.
ARE YOU A VEGETARIAN?
I AM NOT.
(whispers) NOR AM I.
(normal voice) OKAY,
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
CHOPPED CELERY,
ONIONS, AND CARROTS.
SOME GARLIC, LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, CARAWAY SEED.
NICE.
I KIND OF MAKE
A FAUX PASTRAMI BATH,
MAKE IT TASTE AS MUCH
LIKE MEAT AS YOU CAN.
ARBOL CHILE, DRY DILL.
CORIANDER.
THYME, LITTLE BIT OF BAY,
OLIVE OIL FOR THE FAT,
LITTLE BIT OF LEMON JUICE.
THEN WE POUR IN THE WATER.
PUT THE BEETS IN THE WATER.
WE'RE GONNA POACH
THESE BEETS OFF?
YES, SIR. TURN THE HEAT ON, AND
LET 'EM COOK FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
WE REMOVE 'EM
FROM THE BROTH.
THEN YOU'LL SKIN 'EM?
YEP.
OKAY, SO SHOW ME THE SLICE
YOU'RE DOING ON THESE.
I TAKE A NICE 2-INCH DIE CUTTER.
I JUST TAKE OFF THAT EXCESS.
LITTLE BIT OF TRIM OFF THE EDGE
ABOUT A PINKY THICKNESS.
WE SHOULD JUST HAVE
A LITTLE COLD TASTE OF THIS.
I THINK SO, TOO.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. YOU CAN TOTALLY TASTE
THE NOTES OF PASTRAMI.
OH, LET'S DO THIS.
SO IT'S BEET SLIDER TIME.
WE GET THE BUNS
TOASTED OFF.
YOU GET THREE OF THESE
WITH AN ORDER?
YES, SIR. ONCE THESE BUNS
GET NICE AND TOASTED,
WE GO AND THROW ON THAT LOVELY
GREEN GODDESS DRESSING,
RED ONION FOR SOME BITE.
THEN WE GET THESE GUYS
NICE AND SALTED.
JUST GET A NICE SEAR, GET 'EM
HOT ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
AND THE SEAR KIND OF GIVES
THAT RESISTANCE
WHEN YOU GIVE THAT BITE
INTO 'EM, KIND OF A SNAP.
GET 'EM OFF THE GRIDDLE AND ONTO
OUR TOASTED BUNS OVER HERE.
YOU MAKE
THE CHIPS YOURSELVES.
I DO, AND I MAKE THE SEASONING
FOR THE CHIPS.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
MMM, FANTASTIC.
THAT'S OFF THE BEATEN PATH.
BUT IT'S MEATY.
IT'S GOT GREAT TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT THE SPICE TO IT
FOR THE PASTRAMI,
THE ONION, THE GREEN GODDESS,
THE POTATO ROLL.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU
RIGHT NOW.
MY MOM, DAD, AND SISTER
WILL BE HERE LIKE THAT.
I'M GONNA TAKE 'EM OVER
TO WASABI'S,
AND THEY'RE GONNA END UP
OVER HERE.
(laughs)
REALLY GOOD, JERAD.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU, GUY.
THIS GUY IS A GENIUS.
(man) BEET SLIDERS.
THE BEET SLIDERS
ARE EXCELLENT.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BEET SLIDERS READY
FOR TABLE SIX.
IT'S BETTER THAN EATING MEAT.
BUT THEY'RE ROCKIN' THAT, TOO.
WHAT ELSE HAVE YOU HAD?
I'VE HAD THEIR BURGERS...
GOT A GATSBY, TABLE SEVEN.
CHICKEN SANDWICH.
GOT A CHICKEN SANDWICH
FOR YOU.
YOU CAN EXPECT A GOOD VARIETY.
EVERYTHING HERE IS FRESH.
AND THE EXPERIENCE OF COMING
HERE IS REALLY, REALLY FUN.
YOU GUYS ARE IN FOR A TREAT.
PART OF THE FUN
IS ACTUALLY WATCHING JERAD COOK
ON THE GRILL.
JOKE WITH THE CHEFS.
I'M NOT THAT GOOD OF A DANCER,
SO I GOT TO RELY ON THE FOOD.
(laughter)
ALL QUALITY STUFF.
(man)
BACON MUSHROOM SWISS.
JUST THE MOP.
THE MOP.
THE MEAT LOAF IS GREAT. IT'S
ALMOST LIKE MY MOM'S MEAT LOAF.
PORK LOIN TABLE 20.
IT'S ALL COMFORT FOOD
WITH A TWIST.
LIKE THE PORK CHOP BRINED,
SMOKED, AND GRILLED.
OH, MY GOSH.
IT IS WONDERFUL.
'CAUSE THIS DUDE KNOWS PORK.
I WORKED ON A HOG FARM
FOR A LITTLE WHILE, TOO.
WHEN YOU'RE
GONNA COOK PORK,
YOU GOT TO HAVE THE AUTHORITY
RIGHT HERE.
SO WE'RE MAKING THE BRINE
FOR THE PORK CHOPS.
YES, SIR.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA DO A LITTLE
CORIANDER. IT'S ALREADY TOASTED.
LITTLE SUGAR. I DO A LITTLE
LESS SALT THAN SUGAR.
YOU'LL BE SEASONING IT
WHEN IT GOES
ON THE GRIDDLE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
DIG IT.
LITTLE BIT OF BAY LEAF IN THERE
FOR THAT NICE PINEY TASTE,
THYME, LITTLE VANILLA BEAN.
THIS IS MADAGASCAR.
THAT'S WHERE ALL THE COOKIE IS,
THAT LITTLE WAXY TAR.
THAT FLORAL ACCENT THAT SITS IN
THE BACKGROUND OF THE PORK CHOP.
ARE WE ALREADY
INTO FLORAL ACCENT?
WELL, YOU KNOW.
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
GOT TO HAVE ACID.
FAT IS FLAVOR.
ACID IS LIFE.
OOH.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
THE FORCE IS STRONG
IN THIS ONE.
SIMMER IT. LET IT ALL COOK DOWN.
LET IT COOL.
LOOK AT SOME OF THE MARBLING
INSIDE OF THAT.
IT'S A GOOD-LOOKING CHOP
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S NOT YOUR STANDARD
EVERYDAY CHOP.
EVERYDAY BRINE.
POUR IT
RIGHT OVER THE TOP.
HOW LONG WILL YOU LET THIS
SIT THERE AND BRINE?
ABOUT 24 HOURS.
REALLY?
THAT WAY, IT SEEPS IN.
ALL THE FLAVORS MARRY,
AND IT GETS NICE AND JUICY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
OUT TO THE SMOKER.
LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
EVERYTHING'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT HERE AT GATSBY'S.
WHAT KIND OF CHIPS?
WE GOT SOME
APPLE WOOD CHIPS,
COFFEE BEANS
TO ADD RICH BACKGROUND.
IT HAS ALMOST A MOCHA FLAVOR TO
IT. RIGHT ON TOP OF THE COALS.
SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
NOW HOW LONG WE GONNA
PUT SMOKE ON THESE?
FOR ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
BUT YOU'RE GOING
LOW TEMPERATURE.
IT DOESN'T GET OVER 165
IN THERE.
SO WE'RE JUST PERFUMING IT.
THAT'S IT.
LET'S GO. SMOKED CHOP.
SMOKED CHOP.
FIRE IT UP.
SEA SALT,
SOME BLACK PEPPER.
NO OIL?
NO OIL JUST YET.
IT'S GOT ENOUGH FAT IN THERE
AND GET IT NICE
AND CRISPY.
SMELLS LIKE
WE'RE COOKING A HAM.
YEAH, YEAH.
THE JOWLS ARE WARMING UP
RIGHT NOW.
GOT SOME BLUE LAKE
GREEN BEANS.
DID YOU BLANCH
THOSE GREEN BEANS?
I DO. I DO. LITTLE SEA SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
GOT ABOUT TWO,
MAYBE THREE MINUTES HERE.
WE READY TO GO?
YES, WE ARE.
OKAY.
GET THEM GREEN BEANS
OFF OF THERE.
I CAN SMELL THE SMOKE
COMING OFF IT RIGHT NOW.
YEP.
MMM. YOU SEE THAT?
LOOK AT THE JUICE
THAT COMES OUT OF THIS.
THERE'S A REAL GOOD
BALANCE HERE, THE SMOKE,
THE SEASONING, STYLE OF COOKING
OF YOUR PORK CHOP.
MMM. DIG THAT. CONGRATS.
THANKS.
(man)
CENTER CUT PORK CHOP.
IT'S VERY JUICY,
GREAT PIECE OF MEAT.
(woman) THE SMOKE IN IT
IS AWESOME.
CENTER CUT PORK CHOP UP.
IT'S NOT RUN OF THE MILL,
WHICH MAKES IT REALLY FUN.
WE'VE DONE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE UNIQUE,
SMOKED PORK CHOP
AND A BEET SANDWICH.
WHEN WE COME BACK TO GATSBY'S
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA,
THEY'RE GONNA SHOW US
SOME OF THE TRADITIONAL DISHES.
ROULADEN IS UP.
THIS IS OLD
EUROPEAN, DELICIOUS.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THIS.
WELCOME BACK TO GATSBY'S
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA.
NOW WE MADE A SMOKED PORK CHOP
IN THE PARKING LOT
AND A REALLY COOL
BEET SANDWICH.
BUT NOW WE'RE GOING TRADITIONAL,
AND WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE ARE GONNA BE MAKING
A GERMAN BEEF ROULADEN.
MY MOM COOKED A LOT
OF GERMAN FOOD.
ROULADEN WAS ONE OF THOSE.
ROULADEN?
ROULADEN, BEEF ROULADEN.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH SOME
THINLY SLICED LONDON BROIL.
THIS CUT IS CALLED
A BUTTERBALL CUT.
THAT'LL BE THE NICER END
OF THE MEAT RIGHT THERE.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
A GOOD ATTORNEY,
A GOOD BAIL BONDSMAN,
AND A GREAT BUTCHER.
THAT'S IT.
AND NOW
WE'RE GONNA STUFF IT.
THIS IS DIJON MUSTARD,
NICE FRESH SMOKED BACON.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT. RAW
BACON GOING INSIDE OF A ROLL?
IT'S GONNA BE COOKED
THROUGH THOROUGHLY.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME OF OUR
HOMEMADE PICKLES, YELLOW ONION.
WE'RE GONNA GO NEXT
TO OUR GRANULATED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER ON THERE LIKE THAT.
TAKE THIS GUY.
GONNA ROLL HIM UP
JUST LIKE MAKING EGG ROLLS
OR SPRING ROLLS OR SOMETHING.
WE'RE GONNA BE SEARING THESE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT A SKEWER
THROUGH THESE.
PUT TWO OF THESE
ON A PLATE.
HEAVY.
WE'RE GONNA BRAISE THE ROULADEN,
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
RIGHT HERE. WE'RE GONNA
BE TAKING OUR BEEF ROULADEN,
AND WE WANT TO BROWN 'EM
A LITTLE BIT ON EACH SIDE.
GONNA LINE THESE GUYS UP
LIKE LITTLE SOLDIERS IN HERE.
THIS A BIG SELLER?
WE DO SELL QUITE A FEW OF THESE.
WE WANT TO THROW IN SOME ONION.
NOW YOU TURN 'EM AND BROWN 'EM
ON THE OTHER SIDE?
EXACTLY.
PUT A LITTLE CRUST ON 'EM.
GET A LITTLE CARAMELIZATION
GOING THERE WITH THE MEAT.
ADD JUST ENOUGH WATER, BARELY
COVER THE TOP OF THE MEAT.
OKAY.
THEN WE START ADDING
OUR OTHER INGREDIENTS.
PUT IN SOME BEEF BOUILLON,
LITTLE BAY LEAF RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS ACTUALLY
KITCHEN BOUQUET.
LITTLE COLOR.
THIS IS ANOTHER LITTLE THING
WE USE HERE, MAGGI.
MAGGI--LITTLE
SEASONING LIQUID.
PUT A LID ON IT. LET IT GO
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO NOW?
WE ARE GONNA START
ON OUR GERMAN PURPLE CABBAGE.
PURPLE VERSUS...
PINK, GREEN, UH, YELLOW.
MAUVE. I ALWAYS LOVED
MAUVE CABBAGE.
THROW SOME BACON IN HERE.
NOW WHILE THIS IS GOING
AND THE BACON'S GETTING A LITTLE
BIT ON THE CRISPY SIDE,
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND THROW IN SOME YELLOW ONION.
WANT SOME OF THIS ONION
TO GET CARAMELIZED
WITH SOME OF THE COOKED BACON.
GO AHEAD AND DEGLAZE THIS PAN
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF CALIFORNIA RED WINE.
PROBABLY
FROM SONOMA COUNTY.
PROBABLY. ABOUT
2 CUPS OR SO.
CHUG, CHUG, CHUG, CHUG.
THERE WE GO,
SOME BAY LEAF.
WHOLE CLOVE.
CARAWAY SEED. NOW WE'RE READY
TO PUT IN OUR PURPLE CABBAGE.
CUP AND A HALF OF SUGAR,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
GO FOR IT.
LITTLE BIT ON THE EDGE.
THERE WE GO, BEEF BOUILLON.
LITTLE TAD OF WATER.
45 MINUTES TO SIMMER, BREAKS IT
ALL DOWN, NICE AND SOFT.
WE'RE READY TO PLATE
SOME OF THIS STUFF UP HERE.
BOILED PARSLEY
POTATOES, BASIC.
YOU DON'T NEED TO GET REAL FANCY
WITH YOUR POTATOES.
ALL THE FLAVOR IS GONNA BE IN
ALL THIS OTHER FOOD RIGHT HERE.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA PUT ON SOME OF THIS
PURPLE CABBAGE RIGHT HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND LOAD UP ON SOME OF THESE
ROULADENS. THERE WE GO.
OH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA NEED A LADLE.
YOU NEED A LADLE.
WOW.
I WAS CARRYING ONE
WITH ME.
LITTLE BIT OF THIS
REALLY GOOD JUICE RIGHT HERE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
BRING IT OVER HERE.
THIS STUFF YOU DON'T
EVEN NEED A KNIFE.
MMM. SEE THAT'S HOW YOU
PACKAGE DEAL THAT RIGHT THERE.
SUPER TENDER. THERE'S A LOT
OF FLAVOR GOING ON WITH IT.
HERE'S THE KEY
TO EATING THIS.
YOU GOT TO GET A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING, MMM.
THE GRAVY
IS A LITTLE BIT SWEET,
THE MEAT,
GOT A LITTLE SALT TO IT.
YOU GET THE BACON, MMM. THEN YOU
GET THE VIBRANCE OF THE PICKLE.
THIS IS OLD-SCHOOL EUROPEAN. YOU
GOT TO APPRECIATE THAT YOU GUYS
TOOK THE TIME TO MAKE IT
FROM SCRATCH, REALLY NICE.
THANK YOU.
ROULADEN IS UP.
THE SAUCE THAT'S OVER IT
IS REALLY DELICIOUS.
BEEF IS ACTUALLY VERY,
VERY TASTY, NICE COMBINATION
OF THE PICKLE
AND THE MUSTARD.
GOT THE ROULADEN HERE
FOR YOU.
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
THE CABBAGE JUST TOPS IT OFF.
IT'S GOT A REAL SWEETNESS TO IT,
JUST OFFSETS THE TANGINESS
AND THE PICKLES.
IT JUST KNOCKED ME
OUT OF THE PARK.
IT'S A RESTAURANT
THAT WE'RE GONNA START TELLING
ALL OF OUR NEIGHBORS ABOUT.
FIRE BURGER UP.
THE ENVIRONMENT JUST KEEPS
DRAWING ME BACK TO IT.
COMING BACK AND BACK AND BACK.
I LOVE IT VERY MUCH.
TWO GUYS SCRATCH-MAKING
ALL THE FOOD.
GUYS, I GOT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING, GREAT VISIT.
APPRECIATE IT, GUY.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NEXT STOP...
NEED ANYTHING ELSE?
WE'RE HEADING TO WISCONSIN...
HOW'S LUNCH, GUYS?
FOR BIG BURGERS...
THE MEAT IS AS FRESH
AS CAN BE.
YOU JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
NOW YOU KNOW THE NAME
OF THE SHOW.
IT'S
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
AND EVERYBODY'S
GOT THEIR FAVORITE.
YOU GOT YOUR DINER FANS. SOME
PEOPLE GO FOR THE DRIVE-INS.
AND THEN YOU GOT THE FOLKS
WHO JUST LOVE A DIVE,
LIKE A BUNCH OF TRIPLE "D" FANS
IN SUPERIOR, WISCONSIN,
WHO CAN'T TELL ME ENOUGH
ABOUT THEIR FAVORITE DIVE,
A PLACE CALLED
ANCHOR BAR AND GRILL.
I E-MAILED YOU GUYS,
'CAUSE YOU'RE NEVER GONNA SEE
ANOTHER PLACE LIKE IT.
ANCHORBURGER.
I COME TO THIS PLACE
BECAUSE THEY SERVE GOOD FOOD,
BIG PORTIONS,
AND I JUST LOVE IT.
HERE'S YOUR BREAKFAST SHOT.
THANKS.
THE ANCHOR BAR
IS THE PLACE TO BE.
A PLACE A LOT OF TRIPLE "D"
FANS WANT TO BE.
AND TO THEM,
IT'S CLEARLY A DIVE.
JUST ASK OWNER ADAM ANDERSON.
WE'RE A DIVE BAR,
AND WE'RE PROUD OF IT.
AND HE OUGHT TO KNOW.
MUSHROOM AND SWISS.
DAD PURCHASED IT IN 1977,
THE YEAR I WAS BORN.
HOW WAS EVERYTHING, FOLKS?
BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS A KID.
BOTH ARE FRIES, RIGHT?
'STARTED COOKING
WHEN I WAS 15.
THEN AFTER CULINARY SCHOOL
AND COOKING
IN WHITE TABLECLOTH JOINTS...
HOW'S LUNCH, GUYS?
HE SAYS THE FAMILY BUSINESS
CALLED HIM BACK.
I WANT TO KEEP IT GOING,
KEEP IT IN THE FAMILY.
IT'S KIND OF LEGENDARY
AROUND HERE.
RIGHT HERE.
FOR ONE THING,
BIG BURGERS MADE FRESH.
THE MEAT IS AS FRESH
AS CAN BE.
WE GET OUR BEEF FROM
A LOCAL MEATPACKING COMPANY.
THEY GRIND IT
EVERY MORNING,
GET ABOUT 120 POUNDS
UP TO 140 POUNDS A DAY.
18-SOME BURGERS ON THE MENU,
LOTS OF INGREDIENTS...
(Adam) MUSHROOMS ON TOP.
ALL PILED ON THE BURGERS...
SAUERKRAUT ON TOP.
JALAPEÑOS, PILES OF BACON.
PINEAPPLE ON TOP HERE.
THESE BURGERS WILL WARM
YOU UP, WHATEVER YOU ORDER.
AND A BUNCH OF YOU WROTE IN
ABOUT THIS ONE...
(man) OLIVE BURGER.
(woman) IT'S A TON OF CREAM
CHEESE AND GREEN OLIVES.
AND THEN I ADDED BACON,
JUST BECAUSE I LIKE BACON.
AND THIS ONE.
I'M HAVING THE CASHEW BURGER.
I LIKE THE SALTINESS
OF THE CASHEWS ON TOP
OF THE BURGER. IT'S NICE.
(man) HERE YOU GO.
AND THEN THERE'S
THE MEGA FAN FAVORITE.
THAT'S A GALLYBUSTER.
IT'S A POUND OF MEAT,
THREE SLICES OF CHEESE.
GETS ME FULL EVERY TIME.
WHERE CAN YOU GET A 1-POUND
BURGER FOR ONLY $5.50?
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
AND CALIFORNIA BURGER.
I TRY AND ROAD TRIP ALL THE WAY
TO SUPERIOR, WISCONSIN,
JUST FOR THE BURGERS
AND THE NICE ATMOSPHERE HERE.
ENJOY, GUYS.
THIS IS PROBABLY
THE MOST POPULAR,
MOST FAMOUS PLACE IN THE AREA.
BURGER.
AND A LOT OF IT'S
THE FOLKS WHO WORK HERE.
DING DING.
THERE'S WINNIE.
I DING DING WHEN MY FOOD'S DONE,
AND THEY COME AND GET IT
AND TAKE IT OUT. I LOVE IT.
THAT'S A LONG TIME
AGO, JUSTIN.
AND THEN THERE'S "BEAN."
BEEN MANAGING
FOR, LIKE, 32 YEARS.
HER NAME IS JEAN PRETTY.
WE ALL CALL HER "BEAN,"
KIND OF LIKE A SECOND MOM.
YOU'RE NOT A PUP ANYMORE.
THERE'S A LOT OF ATTITUDE HERE.
AND THE LOCALS LOVE IT...
GALLYBUSTER.
THANKS.
ALMOST AS MUCH AS THE FOOD.
SO IF YOU REALLY LOVE BURGERS,
THIS IS THE PLACE TO COME TO.
BACON BURGER.
THESE ARE
THE BEST BURGERS AROUND.
(woman) CALIFORNIA BURGER.
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
YEAH.
THE FOOD'S AWESOME. YOU GOT TO
COME CHECK THIS PLACE OUT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(indistinct
high-pitched voice)
SOMEBODY'S BEEN EATING
A LOT OF BEETS.