HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
PORK'S READY?
PORK'S READY.
PORK-TASTIC.
MMM.
OUTSIDE
SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA...
WHOA.
THE 118-YEAR-OLD
GENERAL STORE...
CHAIN GANG CHILI UP.
LOADING UP CHILI...
CRAZY GOOD.
WITH SMOKED PORK...
THE PULLED PORK
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
LARGE PORK LOVE COMING OUT.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD PIZZERIA...
EVERYTHING IS SO FRESH.
MAKING THEIR OWN MOZ...
MMM.
AND PILING ON THE PORK.
IN THE LEVEL
OF MEGA AWESOME.
AND IN DENVER...
THE GREEN CHILI HERE IS AMAZING.
EVERY BITE
HAS A PIECE OF PORK
THE TRIPLE "D" FAN FAVORITE...
TWO CHILE RELLENOS
IN THE WINDOW.
WHERE VIEWERS SAY
THEY'VE GOT IT ALL...
THE VEGGIE OMELET.
EVEN THE KITCHEN SINK.
HERE'S YOUR
KITCHEN SINK BURRITO.
ANYTHING YOU COULD EVER
WANT TO EAT INSIDE A BURRITO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
SO HERE WE ARE IN MY HOMETOWN
AREA OF NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
NOW WE'RE KNOWN FOR SO MUCH
UP HERE--
I MEAN, THE BEAUTIFUL REDWOODS,
GREAT SEAFOOD,
AND OF COURSE, THE WINE COUNTRY.
NOW ONE OF MY FAVORITE AREAS
IS HERE IN ALEXANDER VALLEY
IN SONOMA COUNTY.
IF YOU'VE BEEN HERE,
WELL, THEN YOU KNOW,
AND PEOPLE HAVE
PROBABLY TOLD YA,
YOU WANT GOOD WINE COUNTRY EATS,
YOU GOTTA CHECK OUT
JIMTOWN STORE.
HERE'S YOUR
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
THE MENU'S AN EXPLOSION OF WHAT
WINE COUNTRY'S ALL ABOUT.
HERE'S YOUR
SPLIT PEA LENTIL SOUP.
SEASONAL AND FRESH
PRODUCE FROM THE GARDEN.
THEY HAVE IT ALL
AND DONE SO WELL.
CHICKEN SALAD.
ALL SERVED UP
IN A COUNTRY STORE.
THANKS SO MUCH.
HAVE A NICE EVENING.
THANK YOU. YOU, TOO.
DISCOVERED 23 YEARS AGO
BY NEW YORKERS CARRIE BROWN...
HERE'S YOUR
SUN-DRIED CHERRY SCONE.
AND HER LATE HUSBAND
JOHN WERNER...
DRIVING DOWN
THIS COUNTRY ROAD,
AND THIS STORE
MADE US PULL OVER.
SO THEY BOUGHT IT,
FIXED IT UP...
POTATO GRATIN FOR YOU.
AND MOVED IN.
THE LITTLE HOUSE IN THE BACK
AND THE GARDEN AND ALL THAT.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S WHERE YOU LIVE?
YES.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE "GREEN ACRES"
FEEL, DOESN'T IT?
CARRIE'S EVEN
GROWING HERBS OUT THERE
THAT CHEF PETER BROWN...
BRISKET AND BUN
GOING IN THE OVEN.
IS USING ALL ACROSS THE MENU,
FROM THE SPLIT PEA SOUP...
SPLIT PEA'S READY TO GO.
TO THE CHICKEN SOPA...
PLATING UP THE SOPA.
EVEN IN THIS FAN FAVORITE...
CHAIN GANG CHILI UP.
HOW IS THE CHILI?
EXCELLENT.
CHILI--DELICIOUS.
PETER'S GOT SOUL.
AND HIS OWN KEY INGREDIENT...
THE SMOKED PORK HAS
A NICE SMOKY, SAVORY FLAVOR.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S MAKE
OUR HOUSE DRY RUB.
AND THIS IS FOR WHAT?
PORK THAT WE PUT
IN OUR CHILI.
IT'S A CORNUCOPIA
OF SEASONINGS AND SPICES.
THIS IS THE ONLY ONE
I'M STUMPED ON.
IT'S BAY LEAF
THAT WE GROW IN THE GARDEN...
FRESH BAY LEAF.
AND GRIND OURSELVES.
A LITTLE BIT GOES A LONG WAY.
OKAY, HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT, START WITH
NEW MEXICO CHILI POWDER...
DIG IT.
GROUND BAY LEAF,
GARLIC POWDER, CUMIN,
GOT SOME DRIED THYME HERE,
A LITTLE POWDERED ONION,
BLACK PEPPER.
YOU WENT AND GROUND THAT FRESH,
DIDN'T YOU?
OH, WE ONLY GRIND IT FRESH.
WE DON'T MESS AROUND.
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR,
ALLSPICE, A LITTLE CINNAMON.
DON'T LET THE STOREFRONT
FOOL YA.
THIS GUY'S GOING FULL CULINARY
BACK HERE.
CLOVE, MUSTARD POWDER,
AND FENNEL SEED,
AND THIS JUST GETS
WHISKED TOGETHER.
OKAY.
THE NICE
BONELESS PORK BUTT.
MM-HMM.
START WITH SOME SALT.
RUB IT DOWN WITH OUR HOUSE RUB
THAT WE MADE.
IT'S A GREAT HOUSE RUB,
MAN.
WE'RE GONNA
LET IT REST OVERNIGHT.
THEN IT GOES
IN THE SMOKER.
OH.
HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA RUN THE PORK?
FIVE HOURS OF SMOKE.
BOY, YOU KEEP
THAT SMOKER CLEAN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE BRAISING LIQUID
TO FINISH THE PORK...
OKAY.
SOME WATER,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR, MOLASSES...
NICE COLOR
OUT OF THAT.
JULIENNE ONION,
A LITTLE CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES,
AND A COUPLE BAY LEAVES.
LET THAT
COME TO A SIMMER.
AND WE'LL GRAB
THE PORK.
YEP.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA POUR THIS
RIGHT OVER THE PORK.
OH.
COVER IT
NICE AND TIGHT.
THE PARCHMENT
AND THE FOIL.
YEAH, YOU WANT TO CREATE
A REALLY NICE SEAL IN THERE.
UH, IT'S PORK.
THAT'S NOT SEAL.
(laughs)
GOT IT ON THERE
NICE AND TIGHT.
INTO THE OVEN
ABOUT THREE HOURS.
PORK'S READY?
PORK'S READY.
OH, I CAN SMELL IT.
RIDICULOUS.
AND THERE IT IS.
LOOK AT THIS.
JUST WATCH.
THAT'S TENDER.
MMM, THAT'S THE WAY TO GO
RIGHT THERE.
NOW ARE WE GONNA
USE THAT LIQUID AGAIN?
IN THE CHILI.
LET'S GET
ON THIS CHILI, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT,
A LITTLE OIL, SAUTéED ONIONS,
AND GARLIC.
THE NEW MEXICO
CHILI POWDER.
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
A LITTLE CUMIN, YEAH,
MEXICAN OREGANO.
BIG FLAVOR.
STIR THAT UP.
ANOTHER ADDITION I REALLY LIKE,
DARK MEXICAN BEER.
MMM.
THAT REALLY JUST COMPLEMENTS
THE CHILI PERFECTLY.
DEGLAZE A LITTLE BIT
WITH THAT.
YOU COOK DOWN. WE'RE
GONNA ADD JUST SOME WATER
FOR OUR DELICIOUS
BRAISING LIQUID...
MMM.
LIQUID FROM THE PORK,
ADD SOME CRUSHED TOMATOES,
OUR PULLED PORK...
CRAZY GOOD.
CHILI-GRIND GROUND BEEF
BROWNED OFF A LITTLE.
THEN WE ADD
OUR FIRE-ROASTED PASILLAS--
GIVE IT A STIR--
AND SOME KIDNEY BEANS,
A PINCH OF SALT.
COOK THIS DOWN
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT AN HOUR.
DOESN'T IT LOOK GOOD?
WHAT'S THE FINAL STEP
HERE, BROTHER?
WE'RE GONNA TIGHTEN IT UP
WITH A LITTLE MASA.
AND NOW
WE'RE READY TO GO?
YEP, READY FOR SOME
CHAIN GANG CHILI.
IS THAT
A NORMAL SERVING?
THAT'S A CUP.
YOU CAN ALSO GET A BOWL,
WHICH IS TWO OF THOSE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'LL HOLD YA.
WOW.
THIS IS STAND-UP CHILI.
OH, YEAH.
MMM, GOSH,
THAT IS GOOD.
THE PULLED PORK,
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
GOOD TEXTURE OF MEAT,
CHILI-GRIND BEEF.
MMM, LOTS OF FLAVOR.
AND THE CHIPS, FORGET ABOUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU GUYS MAKE THESE?
WE DO.
NICE JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
MY KIDS
ARE CHILI JUNKIES.
HUNTER, I'M GONNA BRING YOU
THE REST OF THIS.
HERE'S YOUR
CHAIN GANG CHILI.
IT'S GOT SOME SPICINESS
TO IT.
MEXICAN OREGANO--YOU JUST GET
A LITTLE TOUCH OF IT IN THERE.
IT'S HEARTY. IT'S FILLING,
AND IT'S TASTY.
IT REMINDS ME OF CAMPING.
IT REMINDS ME OF GOOD TIMES,
TIMES WITH FAMILY.
EVERYTHING ABOUT THIS PLACE
IS KIND OF RUSTIC AMERICAN
AS SOON AS YOU WALK IN THE DOOR.
WHETHER YOU'RE EATING...
POTATO GRATIN.
OR SHOPPING...
HOW'S THE SPICY
PEPPER JAM?
OH, IT'S DELICIOUS.
I LOVE IT.
THE WOOD FLOOR,
THE OLD COUNTERS.
WE JUST CAME FROM SCHOOL,
AND WE'RE LOOKING AT THE TOYS.
NICE.
YOU CAN
BUY ANYTHING HERE.
YES, YOU CAN.
(man) I MEAN, WHERE CAN YOU GET
ATOMIC FIREBALLS,
AUTHENTIC TOYS,
WINE COUNTRY WINE,
AND INCREDIBLE FOOD?
THAT'S JIMTOWN.
EVERYTHING HERE IS FROM SCRATCH.
RIGHT DOWN
TO THE SANDWICHES...
JIMTOWN SANDWICH.
LIKE HOMEMADE TAPENADE
FOR THE BRIE AND OLIVE
SANDWICH...
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
FRESH ROASTED TURKEY
FOR THE TURKEY MUSHROOM MELT,
AND THIS HEAVY HITTER...
BARBECUE BRISKET SANDWICH.
THAT TAKES TWO DAYS TO MAKE.
THE MEAT'S REALLY TENDER.
HOW'S THE BRISKET SANDWICH?
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING BRISKET.
THIS IS GONNA BE FOR WHAT?
FOR OUR BRISKET SANDWICH.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT IN HALF,
SEASON IT WELL WITH SALT.
IT'S A BIG PIECE OF MEAT,
SO WE'RE GONNA BE
A LITTLE HEAVY-HANDED.
I LIKE
A LOT OF PEPPER.
ESPECIALLY THAT
NICE FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
OH, YEAH. NOW JUST A LIGHT
TOUCH OF THE HOUSE RUB.
THAT ADDS A LITTLE COLOR
TO THE BARK.
MM-HMM.
SO THESE ARE DONE. NOW TO
THE SMOKER? GOT IT. OKAY.
YEP, LET'S DO IT.
AND HOW MANY HOURS ARE WE GONNA
PUT SMOKE ON THE BRISKET?
ABOUT FOUR HOURS OF SMOKE.
AND WHAT ARE WE RUNNING,
220?
YEP.
AND THEN ANOTHER FOUR
AT THAT TEMPERATURE
TO JUST REALLY
COOK IT DOWN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, TIME TO MAKE
THE BOURBON BARBECUE SAUCE...
MMM.
FOR THE BRISKET SANDWICH--
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL, RED ONION.
AND ONCE THESE ARE NICE
AND SOFT, SOME OF OUR HOUSE RUB,
AND I LIKE TO COOK THAT OUT
IN THE OIL
TO HELP BRING OUT THE FLAVOR
IN THE SPICES.
AND IT ALSO DISSIPATES IT
INTO THE OIL.
ABSOLUTELY.
NEXT, BOURBON.
I LIKE A FAIR AMOUNT OF BOURBON,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
THERE YOU GO.
TEMPER THAT WITH ABOUT
AN EQUAL AMOUNT OF WATER.
OKAY.
NEXT UP.
WE GOT SOME MOLASSES HERE,
A COUPLE BAY LEAVES,
MUSTARD POWDER,
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE, SUGAR.
FINISH IT OFF
WITH SOME KETCHUP.
THE GLUE
OF THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S GONNA COOK DOWN
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 20 TO 30 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT.
THE BRISKET'S COOLED DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
SLICE IT UP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK AT THE NICE BARK
ON THAT. MMM.
SLICE SOME MORE.
LET'S MAKE A SANDWICH.
LET'S DO IT.
WE'RE GONNA START BY ADDING SOME
OF OUR BOURBON BARBECUE SAUCE.
NOW I'M GONNA
ADD THE BRISKET.
REHEAT IT
IN THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
THAT'S CORRECT.
GOT IT.
COAT THE MEAT.
WARM THE MEAT UP.
SOME NICE CARAMELIZED
RED ONION HERE.
AND THEN THIS GOES IN THE OVEN
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
THEN WE'LL PUT THE ROLL
IN THERE, TOO.
READY FOR THE BRISKET SANDWICH?
ALL RIGHT.
ROCK 'N' ROLL, MAN.
SLICE THIS, WE'RE GONNA DO
A LITTLE CHIPOTLE MAYO,
BRISKET.
GOOD-LOOKING SANDWICH, MAN.
AND THESE ARE
SOME GREAT PICKLES,
WHICH ADDS A LITTLE CRUNCH
AND A LOT OF FLAVOR.
AND THIS
IS HOW WE DO IT?
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM. BIG, DEEP,
RICH FLAVOR OF THE BRISKET.
SAUCE IS NO JOKE. YOU GET THAT
LITTLE BACK KICK OF THE BOURBON.
GREAT ROLL FOR IT. IF YOU
WOULD'VE GIVEN ME A CHANCE
TO TELL YA, DON'T PUT PICKLES
ON IT, I WOULD'VE SAID DON'T.
UH-HUH.
HOWEVER, PICKLES
ARE WHAT MAKES IT, MAN.
(laughs)
A LITTLE BIT OF ACID REFRESHES
YOUR PALATE EACH TIME.
ABSOLUTELY.
MM-HMM. EXCELLENT JOB.
HERE'S YOUR
BARBECUE BRISKET SANDWICH.
THE WAY A BRISKET
HAS GOTTA BE DONE.
MMM.
A LITTLE SPICY,
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET.
NICE PICKLES.
THE PICKLES ON THAT--ARE THOSE
OUT OF BOUNDS, OR WHAT?
HAM AND BRIE SANDWICH.
YOU CAN TASTE HOW HOMEMADE
EVERYTHING IS.
IT'S LIKE THE QUINTESSENTIAL
LITTLE FIND.
YOU CAN'T JUST DRIVE BY IT.
YOU JUST HAVE TO STOP.
JIMTOWN SANDWICH.
GREAT STORE,
SUCH GREAT ENERGY BEHIND IT,
AND NOW IT'S NICE TO LEARN
THE STORY. YOU'RE AMAZING.
OH, THANK YOU, GUY.
UP NEXT...
HOT, HOT, HOT.
COMING OUT.
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO SAN ANTONIO...
THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
AND IT'S PORK-TASTIC.
MMM, MEGA AWESOME.
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE FIND SOME OF THE GREATEST
PIZZA JOINTS IN THE COUNTRY.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKING
LUIGI'S IN SAN DIEGO,
VITO & NICK'S IN CHICAGO,
COMET IN D.C.
IT'S GREAT PIZZA
BY GREAT PEOPLE,
AND WE'RE HERE
TO FIND ANOTHER JOINT
HERE IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS.
THIS IS
DOUGH PIZZERIA NAPOLETANA.
HOT, HOT, HOT.
COMING OUT.
IT'S THE BEST PIZZA
IN TOWN.
ARUGULA'S GOING DOWN.
EVERYTHING IS SO FRESH.
(man) PICK IT UP.
THE ULTIMATE TASTE
OF ITALIAN FOOD.
I THOUGHT THAT I WAS
GONNA SEE A GONDOLA GO BY.
MY FAMILY'S FROM NAPLES.
THIS PIZZA IS LIKE GOING HOME.
BECAUSE OWNER DOUG HORN...
COMING OUT.
REALLY MAKES 'EM
THE NEAPOLITAN WAY.
NICE.
THE RIGHT FLOUR,
THE RIGHT TOMATOES,
THE RIGHT TECHNIQUES,
AND THE RIGHT OVEN--
HOW THEY USED TO DO IT
300 YEARS AGO.
AND THE WAY
DOUG AND HIS WIFE LORI...
HOW'S EVERYTHING...
HAS BEEN DOING IT
SINCE THEY OPENED THIS JOINT
THREE YEARS AGO.
PICK UP.
WE GET COMMENTS,
"IT'S THE BEST PIZZA I'VE HAD
SINCE I WAS IN ITALY."
(man) THERE WE GO.
JUST THE QUALITY OF THE FOOD
IS JUST INCREDIBLE.
FROM THE BASICS...
THE MARGHERITA IS FABULOUS.
(man) MARINARA.
IT'S REAL RICH
AND TASTES GREAT.
TO ONE
WITH A PORK-TASTIC TWIST...
LARGE PORK LOVE COMING OUT.
(man) JUST ABOUT
EVERY KIND OF PORK
YOU CAN GET, WANT OR HAVE.
AND THE CRUST
IS FANTASTIC.
GONNA MAKE OUR PIZZA DOUGH
FOR THE DAY.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A FORK MIXER.
AS MANY JOINTS AS WE'VE SHOT
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE'VE NEVER SEEN
THE SUPER MEGATRON,
OVERRIDE, ROBOTIC
DOUGH-MAKING MACHINE.
FANTASTIC.
WATER, SICILIAN SEA SALT...
EVERYTHING'S IMPORTED.
EVERYTHING--THE YEAST,
SPECIALTY FLOUR.
SO NOBODY
FALLS IN THERE.
LOOK HOW
GENTLE IT IS.
FORK MIXERS
DON'T HEAT THE DOUGH UP.
YOU REALLY NEED
A LITTLE BIT OF TIME
TO DEVELOP THAT RUSTIC FLAVOR
IN YOUR DOUGH.
ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
NOW IT'S DONE.
WE LET IT REST.
THEN WE PORTION IT OUT?
YEAH.
WHAT'S NEXT, MY BROTHER?
ITALIAN-STYLE SAUSAGE.
START OFF
WITH SOME PORK BUTT.
HE'S ICED THE BOWL.
KEEPING EVERYTHING COLD
WHEN YOU MIX IT UP,
YOU'RE GONNA GET REALLY
NICE CLEAN CUTS ON THE MEAT,
STRAIGHT-UP FAT.
STRAIGHT-UP BACK FAT,
CUT SOME PANCETTA...
ITALIAN BACON
WITHOUT THE SMOKE.
CALABRIAN PEPPERS--THEY'VE GOT
A NICE WARM HEAT TO 'EM--
KOSHER SALT, FINE GROUND PEPPER,
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
FENNEL POLLEN,
CRUSHED CHILI FLAKES,
AND TOASTED FENNEL.
WHICH IN ITALIAN SAUSAGE,
IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS YOU LOVE.
WE'LL LET THAT COOL DOWN.
WE'LL GRIND IT.
FIRE IT UP.
DOWN WE GO.
LOOK AT THAT,
AND LISTEN TO IT,
THAT NICE WHITE FAT
COMING OUT OF THERE.
THIS IS A PRO
DOING HIS JOB.
NOW WE EMULSIFY
WITH A LITTLE WATER NOW.
ADD THE GROUND MEAT
TO THE SAUSAGE STUFFER.
TIME TO GO.
TAKE A HARD CASING,
AND WE JUST LAUNCH.
LOOK AT THAT. RUN ALL
THE CASING OUT. TIE 'EM ALL OFF.
JUST SO IT'S BIG ENOUGH
TO GET IN A ROASTING PAN.
(sizzling)
ROAST 'EM OFF
IN THE OVEN?
THAT'S CORRECT.
OKAY.
WE'RE MAKING MOZZARELLA.
ADD A BLEND OF HOT WHOLE MILK
AND SALTED WATER.
MELT THE CURD.
NOW PUSH IT AROUND.
LET IT START TO ABSORB
SOME OF THIS.
I CAN'T RESIST.
(laughs)
YOU CAN FEEL IT
JUST STARTING TO COME TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA
DRAIN THIS OFF.
IT'S ALREADY COOLED DOWN BECAUSE
IT ABSORBED INTO THE CHEESE.
WE REALLY WANT
SOME HOT MILK IN THERE.
THAT'S GOOD. LET IT BUILD.
WE'RE GONNA STRETCH IT UP.
IT'D BE EASIER IF YOU MILKED
A COW AND THIS CAME OUT.
(laughs)
LIKE THE PIZZA DOUGH,
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT INTO ITSELF.
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT,
AND THEN I JUST PINCH IT OFF.
THAT'S IT.
INTO SOME ICE WATER.
LET IT JUST
SEIZE UP A LITTLE BIT.
AND NOW WE'LL CUT IT UP
FOR THE PORK LOVE PIZZA.
MMM.
I'M MOVING IN.
SAUSAGE LOOKS GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
LET IT REST,
SO WHEN YOU CUT INTO IT,
YOU DON'T LOSE
ALL THE JUICE.
THAT'S CORRECT.
SO THE TOMATO SAUCE...
IT'S SAN MARZANO TOMATOES,
SICILIAN SEA SALT.
THAT'S IT.
WHY MESS WITH IT?
ALL RIGHT,
TO MAKE THE PIZZA,
A LITTLE FLOUR PERFECTLY
PROOFED UP, READY TO GO.
I ONLY GOT
ONE SET OF CLOTHES.
I'M JUST GONNA...
THERE WE GO.
TOMATO SAUCE...
PUSH IT
OUT TO THE EDGE,
THE HOUSE-MADE MOZZARELLA,
THIN-SLICED PANCETTA,
SOPRESSATA SALAMI, OUR SAUSAGE
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
FINISH IT OFF
WITH SMOKED PROSCIUTTO.
YOU GET A TAIL
AND A SNOUT,
YOU'LL HAVE THE WHOLE PIG
ON THERE.
WE'RE RUNNING
ABOUT 800 DEGREES.
WATCH HOW FAST
THIS STARTS TO FIRE OFF.
LET THE BOTTOM OF THAT CRUST
SEIZE UP, SPIN IT.
CRAZY. THAT THING'S
ROCKIN' HOT. (whistles)
WICKED FAST.
YOU'RE GETTING A LITTLE BIT
OF BURN SPOTS,
BUT THAT'S PART OF THE FLAVOR.
THAT'S AWESOME.
ONTO THE PLATE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
IN THE LEVEL
OF MEGA AWESOME.
THE CRUST
IS THE FOUNDATION.
IT'S LIGHT, BUT IT'S FIRM,
AND IT'S GOT TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT NICE CHEW TO IT.
ALL THE MEATS--
JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT, YOU CUT
IT SO THIN THAT IT CRISPS UP,
ALL WORKING TOGETHER
AND JUST MELT IN YOUR MOUTH
WITH THAT CREAMINESS
OF THE MOZZARELLA, MMM.
TOO BAD
YOU DIDN'T WANT ANY.
(laughs)
TRUE COMMITMENT
TO DOING IT THE RIGHT WAY.
ABSOLUTELY.
OFF THE HOOK.
HERE'S YOUR
PORK LOVE PIZZA.
NICE MIXTURE OF SPICE
AND SAVORY, RICH, DECADENT.
THE CRUST IS MADE TO PERFECTION.
OKAY, WE'RE GOING IN.
(woman) THAT OVEN IS AMAZING.
HE'S BROUGHT THAT ALL THE WAY
FROM NAPLES, ITALY.
(Guy) AS SOON AS YOU SEE THAT
WOOD-FIRED OVEN, I CAN SEE
THE COLOR INSIDE, AND I KNOW
THAT THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
COMING OUT.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE OVEN
AND USING FABULOUS,
FRESH INGREDIENTS.
LIKE THE TOPPINGS THEY'RE
LOADING ON THIS FAN FAVORITE...
I'VE GOT
A PULLED PROSCIUTTO PIZZA
THIS IS AMAZING.
LEEKS AND OLIVES
AND ONIONS.
AND DOUG'S PROSCIUTTO
IS THE BEST.
LET'S GO.
TAKE THESE NUBS
OF THE PROSCIUTTO.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A LITTLE
STOCK--CARROTS, CELERY...
SO A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
ONION, GARLIC, WATER.
WE'RE GONNA SLOW-COOK
FOR ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
PULL IT, CHOP IT,
AND PUT IT ON THE LINE
READY FOR THE PIZZA.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
THESE ARE THE MELTED LEEKS--
CREAM, WINE--
GRATED FONTINA--
NOT TOO MUCH--
PULLED PROSCIUTTO--THAT,
I LIKE TO ADD LITTLE EXTRA.
DYNAMITE.
IF YOU LIKE PROSCIUTTO,
THIS IS A TEXTURE THAT YOU
PROBABLY HAVEN'T TRIED BEFORE.
OH.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
ROSEMARY-MARINATED OLIVES,
FRESH ROSEMARY...
WOW, HUGE FLAVOR.
READY TO GO.
YOU JUST HEAR IT START
TO SNAP AND CRACKLE IN THERE.
AND OUT WE GO.
MMM. THAT LOOKS TOO GOOD
TO EVEN EAT.
MMM. AWESOME PIZZA.
SO MUCH DEPTH OF FLAVOR
AND SO MUCH UNIQUE FLAVOR.
THAT FRESH ROSEMARY
RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
THE SWEETNESS OF THE LEEKS,
BRININESS OF THE OLIVES.
I LOVE THE TEXTURE
OF THE PROSCIUTTO.
MMM, AWESOME,
AWESOME, AWESOME.
(woman)
LARGE PULLED PROSCIUTTO PIZZA.
OH, IT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
(man) THE COMBINATION
OF THE MEAT
AND THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND THE LEEKS--MMM, GREAT.
OKAY, SO WE TRIED
SOME GREAT PIZZA HERE AT DOUGH
IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS.
WHEN WE GET BACK, AN ITALIAN
ANTIPASTO CLASSIC, THE...
ROLLATINI.
ALL MY FAVORITE THINGS WRAPPED
UP IN ONE NICE LITTLE PRESENT.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
PICK IT UP.
AT DOUGH,
IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS...
I'M WORKING ON THE NEXT ONE.
OWNER DOUG HORN IS ALL ABOUT
HANDMADE ITALIAN CLASSICS...
COMING OUT.
FROM THE PIZZA...
MARGHERITA, PLEASE.
TO THE MOZZARELLA...
AND I'M UP.
TO THIS TRADITIONAL
ANTIPASTO...
BLACK TRUFFLE ROLLATINI.
ALL MY FAVORITE THINGS WRAPPED
UP INTO ONE NICE LITTLE PRESENT.
HE'S GOT THE PROSCIUTTO WITH IT.
AND THAT LITTLE BLACK TRUFFLE
IS FABULOUS.
START ME OFF, BROTHER.
TAKE CURD, HOT MILK,
AND SALTED WATER--
GOT MOZZARELLA.
EVERY TIME YOU
MAKE ONE OF THESE,
IT GOES THROUGH
THIS PROCESS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
STRETCH THIS INTO MOZ.
SIT IN THE WATER WHILE
WE DICE UP BLACK TRUFFLES,
FLAVOR JETS
JUST WENT ON.
WHERE DO YOU GET
YOUR TRUFFLES FROM?
ITALY. BLENDING IN
THE TRUFFLES.
REALLY AFFECT THE FLAVOR
OF THE MOZZARELLA.
WE'LL ROLL THIS OUT
INTO A SHEET.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHEN IT'S ABOUT
1/8 OF AN INCH THICK,
TAKE BABY ARUGULA,
THEY'RE STILL ALIVE.
TRIM IT RIGHT DOWN.
DRIZZLE BLACK TRUFFLE OIL.
SHAVE SOME PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO
RIGHT OVER THE TOP...
MMM.
LEMON.
HANG ON, HANG ON, HANG ON.
WHAT IS THIS STUFF?
OH, IT'S PROSCIUTTO.
NICE AND SWEET.
YES, IT IS.
I'D WEIGH, LIKE, 9,000 POUNDS
IF I WORKED HERE.
ROLL THIS UP.
OH, THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
WRAP THIS.
SET UP A LITTLE BIT.
(speaking indistinctly)
IT'S GONNA BE SERVED TOASTED
WITH OUR ROLLATINI.
PLATE UP--
ARUGULA DRESSED WITH LEMON,
GARLIC OIL, AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA START LAYERING DOWN.
NICE, THIN SHEETS
OF THAT MOZZARELLA.
OH, THAT TRUFFLE.
ZESTED LEMON,
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
SO YOU MAKE, LIKE,
ONE DISH A YEAR?
LOOK HOW LONG THIS TAKES.
TRUFFLE OIL.
AS BIG AS IT IS, AND AS DENSE,
IT'S VERY LIGHT.
MMM, I'M ACTUALLY
A LITTLE BIT SPEECHLESS.
YOU GET
THIS ENORMOUS FLAVOR,
BUT IT JUST MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH SO QUICKLY.
IT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S JUST SUCH A NICE PRESENCE
OF THE TRUFFLE.
THE OIL WITH THE TRUFFLE INSIDE
OF THE MOZZARELLA ITSELF,
A TOUCH OF THE SALTINESS
AND THE SWEETNESS
OF THE PROSCIUTTO,
A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON ZEST,
BECAUSE IT NEEDS
THAT TOUCH OF ACID.
I MEAN, I CAME HERE
FOR THE PIZZA.
I'LL COME BACK
FOR THE ROLLATINI.
BLACK TRUFFLE ROLLATINI.
YOU WANT TO SAVOR
ALL THE LAYERS.
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE COMBINATION,
PERFECT.
STARTING TO ROLL HERE
WITH THIS.
HE'S THE KING OF MOZZARELLA.
YOU'RE MAKING CHEESE
ALL DAY LONG.
'CAUSE HE'S TOPPING IT WITH
RICOTTA AND FRESH HERBS...
THE BEST CHEESE I'VE EVER HAD.
WRAPPING IT WITH ROASTED
ZUCCHINI AND PANCETTA,
AND HE'S EVEN STUFFING
MOZZARELLA WITH MOZZARELLA.
CASTLE HILLS BURRATA.
AND THEY PUT CREAM IN THERE--
JUST AMAZING.
OKAY, SO WHAT
ARE WE MAKING?
THIS IS
THE CASTLE HILLS BURRATA.
THIS IS SAN ANTONIO
CASTLE HILLS?
YES.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE FILLING FOR IT...
MOZZARELLA.
MMM. I'VE HAD, LIKE, 90 POUNDS
OF CHEESE ALREADY.
HEAVY CREAM, SEA SALT,
AND A LITTLE...
FRESH CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
WE'LL HOLD THIS ON THE SIDE
TO MAKE SOME MORE MOZZARELLA.
MMM.
THAT'S LIKE BUNGEE JUMPING
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
NOT TOO THIN,
1/4 OF AN INCH.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE FILLING
FOR IT JUST LIKE THAT.
MAKE SURE THERE'S
PLENTY OF CREAM,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
OH.
FLIP IT OVER. PINCH IT.
THERE'S A BEAUTIFUL BURRATA.
THAT SHOULD BE ILLEGAL.
LET IT SET,
BUT I LIKE IT TO BE WARM.
THESE ARE HEIRLOOM TOMATOES,
KIND OF LIKE OUR CAPRESE.
CAPRESE GONE WILD.
HOUSE-MADE PESTO.
A LITTLE BASIL OIL.
IT HAS
A REAL VIBRANT COLOR.
NICE LITTLE SPRIG OF BASIL
ON THE TOP,
SEA SALT, PEPPER,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
GORGEOUS.
NOW HOW DO YOU
DIG INTO THIS?
GO RIGHT IN THERE.
GRAB A PIECE OF TOMATO.
GO IN ON THE BREAD.
MMM.
DUDE, YOU'RE WRECKING IT
FOR EVERYBODY.
(laughs)
I MEAN, IT'S RIGHTEOUS,
GOING THAT EXTRA STEP,
GETTING THE HEIRLOOMS.
MAKING THE MOZZARELLA,
THEN SHREDDING THE MOZZARELLA.
MMM. THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
WELL, YOU GET INTO
EVERY SINGLE PIECE OF THIS
LIKE YOU'RE SERVING IT
TO YOUR MOM.
IT'S IMPORTANT.
THE MAN.
PICK UP
A CASTLE HILLS BURRATA.
IT'S ONE
OF THOSE PERFECT DISHES.
(woman) EXCELLENT,
JUST OUT OF THIS WORLD.
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
PICK UP.
WONDERFUL, FRESH,
AUTHENTIC FOOD.
PICKUP ON ARUGULA
AND PROSCIUTTO
AND A MARGHERITA, PLEASE.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP...
ANYTHING YOU COULD
EVER WANT TO EAT.
WE'RE HEADING TO DENVER...
THE VEGGIE OMELET.
FOR GREEN CHILI
TRIPLE "D" VIEWERS
JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
THE GREEN CHILI HERE IS AMAZING.
EVERY BITE HAS A PIECE OF PORK.
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D,"
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHERE I'M GONNA SHOW UP.
I MEAN, IT COULD BE A GREEK
PLACE LOOKING FOR SOME GYROS,
OR IT COULD BE A GREEN CHILI
JOINT IN NEW MEXICO
OR A BURGER SPOT
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE.
NOW I'M GETTING
A WHOLE STACK OF E-MAILS
TELLING ME ABOUT A JOINT
IN DENVER, COLORADO,
THAT'S BRINGING ALL THOSE
GREAT FAVORITES TOGETHER.
HERE IS WHAT FOLKS ARE SAYING
ABOUT SAM'S NO. 3.
HERE'S YOUR
KITCHEN SINK BURRITO.
ANYTHING YOU COULD EVER
WANT TO EAT INSIDE A BURRITO
FROM THE GREEN CHILI
TO A GYRO.
WE GOT A HAMBURGER
MEDIUM.
THE FOOD
IS ALWAYS FANTASTIC.
VEGGIE OMELET.
AND NOTHING'S BETTER THAN SAM'S.
FROM WHAT YOU GUYS
ARE TELLING ME
IS A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
GOT TWO DOGS WET.
AMERICAN STAPLE FOOD...
GREEN CHILI MEXI-BURGER.
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF MEXICAN TWIST ON IT.
AND CHICKEN SOUVLAKI
GREEK SALAD.
THEY HAVE GREAT GREEK FOOD.
HUEVOS, HOME FRIES.
IT'S A MIX OF DIFFERENT
CULTURES, AND I JUST LOVE
THAT THEY'VE KEPT THIS BUSINESS
GOING FOR SO MANY YEARS.
THEY ARE SPERO ARMATAS...
GRETCHEN, GOOD TO SEE YOU.
AND HIS THREE SONS, PATRICK...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS,
HERE WE GO.
ALEX...
WHAT DO YOU GOT WORKING,
SAM?
AND SAM...
WE GOT TWO CHILE RELLENOS
IN THE WINDOW.
A FAMILY OUR VIEWERS HAVE BEEN
DROPPING IN ON FOR GENERATIONS.
MY FATHER STARTED SAM'S NO. 3
IN 1927.
AND I TOOK IT OVER FROM MY DAD.
THEN 12 YEARS AGO,
HIS SONS JOINED IN...
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS,
HERE WE GO.
AND THEY'RE STILL SERVING UP
WHAT GRANDDAD MADE FAMOUS.
RED CHILIES UP.
IT'S MY FAVORITE RED CHILI
OUT THERE.
RED CHILI CHEESE FRIES.
OUR DAD TAUGHT THAT RECIPE
TO US.
TAUGHT 'EM THIS ONE, TOO...
GREEN CHILI--WE TOOK IT,
AND WE MODIFIED IT
TO FIT OUR STYLE,
WHICH WAS A LITTLE MORE KICK.
THEN GAVE IT A NAME
TO MATCH...
THE KICKIN' GREEN CHILI.
YEAH, THEY CALL IT
KICKIN' GREEN CHILI.
THE GREEN CHILI HERE IS AMAZING.
JUST CHECK THE E-MAILS.
IT MAKES EVERYTHING
TASTE BETTER.
YOU NEED A CHILI FIX.
I THINK I DO.
THEY MAKE IT THEMSELVES.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ABOUT SAM'S.
(Sam) EVERY BITE
HAS A PIECE OF PORK.
WE SPICE THE CHILI
WITH SOME SALT, MINCED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER, GROUND MUSTARD,
AND GREEK OREGANO.
THEN THE TOMATOES,
AND FOR THE KICK...
JALAPEÑOS, CHILI PURéE
OUT OF THE FRESH CHILIES,
FRESH ROASTED GREEN CHILIES
THAT WE'VE DICED UP.
WE STIR IT UP.
IT'S READY TO GO.
YOU COULD PUT THAT ON ANYTHING,
AND I WOULD EAT IT.
AND THEY DO, LOADING UP
ALL THE FAVORITES.
PUT IT IN ALL
OUR BREAKFAST BURRITOS...
CHILE RELLENOS--
IT'S JUST FANTASTIC.
AND OUR MEXI-BURGER,
WHICH IS ONE
OF OUR MOST POPULAR DISHES.
GREEN CHILI MEXI-BURGER.
IT'S PRETTY AWESOME.
IT'S HAMBURGER IN A TORTILLA...
THE BURGER HAS A NICE CHAR
ON IT, WHICH IS FABULOUS.
SMOTHERED WITH GREEN CHILI,
AND THEN YOU GET FRIES.
THE FRIES ARE ALSO
SMOTHERED IN CHILI AND CHEESE,
AND I REALLY HAVE TO EAT
A LOT OF IT EVERY TIME I COME.
MINI GREEK SALAD, PLEASE.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC,
AND THE SERVICE IS GREAT.
HERE'S YOUR DELICIOUS BURGER.
IT'S JUST A GREAT FAMILY. I JUST
LOVE GIVING THEM MY BUSINESS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR COMING IN TODAY.
I THINK
THE WHOLE WORLD SHOULD KNOW
WHAT GREAT FOOD SAM'S NO. 3 HAS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
ALL THIS DESIGN
THAT YOU GUYS PUT IN HERE.
WONDERFUL.
NEVER GETS OLD.