HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
BRISKET FRITO PLATTER.
QUIRKY CLASSICS.
OUT OF BOUNDS.
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
THIS IS GONNA BE
STARTED NEXT.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD BISTRO...
EVERY KIND OF FOOD
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
BRINGING BURGERS...
(man) THEN I'LL ADD
MY RED HOT SAUCE.
GONNA BE SMOKIN'.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
MMM. THAT THING'S ROCKIN'.
IN PHILADELPHIA...
SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
THE CORNER CAFE...
THE MENU'S AMAZING.
CORNED BEEF REUBEN.
MIXING JEWISH CLASSICS...
MATZO BALL SOUP.
WITH A LITTLE
SOUTHERN COMFORT.
CHICKEN CHILI FRITO PIE.
MMM. I'D ORDER THAT
AGAIN IN A HEARTBEAT.
AND IN
MANDEVILLE, LOUISIANA...
IT HITS THE SPOT
EVERY TIME.
THE FAMILY JOINT...
CHARLES, HOW YOU DOING?
WHERE THE CHEF...
VOODOO BENEDICT.
IS SERVING UP LOCAL FLAVOR...
THOSE ARE MONEY!
ALL RIGHT!
AND THEN SOME.
I CAN DANCE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ABOUT A MILE SOUTH
OF DOWNTOWN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON,
IN THE LOWER-SOUTH HILL
NEIGHBORHOOD,
IN THE MIDDLE
OF A BUNCH OF NEIGHBORHOODS
IS A FUNKY LITTLE
SHOPPING CENTER.
THEY GOT A GROCERY STORE,
A PIZZA JOINT, A BARBER SHOP,
AND A RESTAURANT THAT'S
SERVING UP SCRATCH-MADE FOOD.
THIS IS
PICABU NEIGHBORHOOD BISTRO.
GORGONZOLA PENNE PASTA.
DELICIOUS FOOD.
PAD THAI'S UP.
MY FAVORITE. VERY GOOD.
MMM. I LOVE THE FALAFEL.
THOSE ARE DISHES
YOU DON'T NORMALLY FIND
IN YOUR EVERYDAY
NEIGHBORHOOD BISTRO.
CURRY BOWL WITH TOFU.
IT'S TRULY ECLECTIC.
'CAUSE THAT'S THE WAY OWNER
JANE EDWARDS...
DID I NEED TO ASK?
LIKES TO EAT.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THE FOOD TO PEOPLE?
A SMALL MENU
BUT A HUGE VARIETY.
THIS IS GONNA BE
STARTED NEXT.
ALL SERVED UP BY LINE COOK
TONY ENGLERT.
YOU GUYS DO THE WHOLE MENU
THE ENTIRE DAY?
YES.
FIRE PASTA.
A WHOLE LOT OF FLAVORS
IN ONE PLACE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT THEY DO
WITH FLAVOR.
HUMMUS.
CILANTRO HUMMUS--
VERY TASTY.
KUNG PAO BEEF'S UP.
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE
TO GET IT.
CACTUS BURGER.
PHENOMENAL. THE MOST UNIQUE
BURGER I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU GET A NICE MIX
OF PEPPERS, ONIONS.
ALL TOPPED OFF
WITH A SIGNATURE SAUCE.
I LOVE THEIR GOO.
GOO?
GOO.
CALLED HAMBURGER GOO?
THAT'S OUR REMOULADE NOW--
WE CALL IT GOO.
OH, I LIKE IT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
OUR BLACKENING SEASONING
GOES IN OUR GOO.
SUGAR.
WHAT, SUGAR?
MM-HMM.
IN THE BLACKENING
SEASONING?
EXACTLY. CAYENNE PEPPER.
WHAT YOU TALKING ABOUT?
PAPRIKA, SALT...
GRANULATED GARLIC.
THANK YOU.
CHILI POWDER.
GROUND ROSEMARY,
THYME, ONION POWDER.
SUGAR?
THE SUGAR ACTUALLY HELPS.
WELL, THE SUGAR BLACKENS.
AND THAT IS OUR
BLACKENED SEASONING.
INTERESTING,
WITH THE SUGAR.
NOW WE ARE GOO-IFYING.
WE ARE MAKING GOO.
CAPERS, SWEET PICKLES.
SMALL...
GREEN ONION.
THIS IS A FUNKY SAUCE.
THIS IS A REALLY GOOD ONE,
ACTUALLY.
GET THAT GRIND UP TO A PRETTY
GOOD PASTE. THERE WE GO.
OKAY.
WE ADD OUR MAYO.
WHOO-HOO.
NOW WE ADD OUR PASTE, TARRAGON,
KETCHUP, DIJON MUSTARD,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
SOY SAUCE, PAPRIKA.
NICE LITTLE
RED HUE TO IT.
OH, YEAH.
HOT SAUCE.
TABASCO,
BLACKENING SEASONING.
AND THE WONDER SPICE.
THERE YOU GO. MIX THAT ALL UP,
AND THIS IS IT.
AS THIS SPENDS A LITTLE TIME,
MARRY MORE IN THE FLAVOR.
EXACTLY.
ALL THE FLAVORS.
IT'S NICE. ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO MAKE THE BURGER.
CACTUS BURGER--START IT
WITH ONE OF OUR PATTIES,
START MY CACTUS TOPPING--
GARLIC BUTTER AND SOME BACON.
OKAY.
BURGERS GONNA GET
ANY SALT OR PEPPER?
WE GO WITH A LITTLE...
IS THAT SOME
OF THE BLACKENING SPICE?
YES.
PEPPER, ONION MIX,
PEPPERONCINIS AS WELL.
GREAT.
WE'LL LET THAT GO AHEAD
AND CRISP UP A LITTLE BIT.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE, AND THEN
I'LL ADD MY RED HOT SAUCE.
THIS THING'S GONNA
BE SMOKIN'.
LET THAT REDUCE.
THAT BURGER READY
TO FLIP?
IT IS. WE JUST BUTTER
AND LIGHTLY TOAST THESE.
GO AHEAD AND THROW
PEPPER JACK ON.
OH, GOSH, THIS THING
DOESN'T STOP.
PULL MY BUN OFF. ALL RIGHT.
SO HAMBURGER GOO GOES DOWN.
BABY LETTUCES.
MM-HMM, TOMATO
AND RED ONION.
CHILI.
WITH FETA AND CILANTRO.
BURGER'S READY?
BURGER'S READY.
OH, THAT SAUCE
LOOKS AWESOME.
AND THAT IS OUR
CACTUS BURGER.
WANT THE REST OF THAT?
PAN WAS HOT.
ALL RIGHT, I GOTTA CUT THIS.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT THING'S ROCKIN'.
LOT OF SPICE AND BIG FLAVOR.
THAT PEPPER, PEPPERONCINI,
HOT SAUCE, BACON CONCOCTION--
NEED TO SERVE THAT
WITH A ROLAIDS MILKSHAKE
AND A DROP CLOTH.
NAILED IT.
THANKS.
CACTUS BURGER...
IT'S JUST REALLY
SATISFYING AND MEATY.
IT'S SPICY.
YOU GOT A LITTLE SWEAT
GOING ON, DON'T YOU?
YEAH, MAN. LOOK AT ALL THIS
ON THERE, MAN. IT'S DELICIOUS.
ABOUT 30 SECONDS
ON THE FIRE PASTA.
ALL THE FOOD HERE
IS SO GREAT.
ALL RIGHT.
HOW DID YOU GUYS
FIND IT?
WE LIVE TWO BLOCKS AWAY.
THANK YOU.
YOU CAN WALK HERE.
WELL, GIRLS, HOW ARE YOU
DOING TODAY?
WE'RE ALWAYS RUNNING
INTO PEOPLE WE KNOW.
COME ON, GET GOING.
ALL PART OF THE PLAN.
MMM.
WE WANTED A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
COULD COME HANG OUT...
YOU WANT SOME?
EVERYBODY WOULD BE HAPPY.
BREAKFAST OF CHAMPIONS.
A TRUE NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
WITH FOOD FROM ALL OVER.
EVERY KIND OF FOOD
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
FALAFEL FOR TABLE FIVE.
IT'S JUST FANTASTIC.
HOW LONG ON THAT REUBEN?
RIGHT NOW.
POT STICKERS.
COMING UP.
EVEN THIS CHINESE CLASSIC.
POT STICKERS
ARE DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE POT STICKER NOW?
WE ARE.
OKAY, ROCK IT OUT, BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT, THROW
OUR FLOUR IN, CORNSTARCH.
BEAUTIFUL COMBO.
AND SALT. LET THIS GO,
JUST ADD WATER AS NEEDED.
JUST STARTING TO PULL AWAY
FROM THE BOWL A LITTLE BIT.
HOLD THE SIDE OF THE BOWL.
WRAP UP MY DOUGH.
OKAY.
OKAY. LET IT REST...
30 MINUTES.
OUR NEXT STEP IS GONNA BE
OUR CHICKEN.
AND THIS IS GONNA BE
FOR OUR FILLING, I TAKE IT?
WHOLE BREAST,
AND THEN CUT 'EM DOWN.
YES.
WHAT I'M ACTUALLY GONNA DO--
I'M GONNA GRIND THIS FIRST.
POP THIS A FEW TIMES.
YEAH. I GO AHEAD AND JUST ADD
MY CILANTRO, GREEN ONION.
GARLIC.
GINGER.
MESS OF IT.
LIME JUICE AND SOY SAUCE.
SO I'LL GO AHEAD AND JUST
LET THAT BUZZ FOR A SECOND.
YOU WANT TO HAVE
SOME TEXTURE.
RIGHT, YOU DO.
ALL RIGHT.
SO THAT COMES IN
AT THE VERY END.
CORN--THAT'S
AN INTERESTING MOVE.
SO THIS ALL COMES TOGETHER,
YOU LET THE FLAVORS MARRY,
AND WHAT'S OUR NEXT STEP?
THROW DOWN SOME FLOUR.
WE HAVE TO ROLL OUT OUR DOUGH.
THEY MAKE AN AWESOME
PASTA ROLLING ATTACHMENT
FOR THE KitchenAid.
I'D LOVE TO SEE THAT.
YES, I BET YOU WOULD.
GO AHEAD AND KNEAD
THIS OUT.
YOU'RE GOING THIN, RIGHT?
AS THIN AS WE
CAN POSSIBLY GO.
SO THIN, IT ONLY HAS
ONE SIDE.
RIGHT.
OKAY, NOW JUST CUT OUT
MY CIRCLES. THAT IS IT.
KEEP 'EM FLOURED SO THEY
DON'T STICK TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND FILL THESE.
NOW WHAT'S THE METHOD HERE?
I PINCH THE CENTER,
PINCH THE ENDS,
SO THEY DON'T
RUN OUT THE SIDES.
BUT THAT DOUGH'S
MOIST ENOUGH
THAT YOU DON'T NEED TO ADD
ANYTHING INTO IT.
NO.
THAT'S HOT, DUDE.
PUT SOME CORNSTARCH DOWN
SO THEY DON'T STICK.
KEEP LOADING THEM UP
ON THAT PLATE.
EXACTLY.
NEXT STEP--
THE DIPPING SAUCE
FOR THE POT STICKERS.
YES. SOY SAUCE, WATER,
RICE VINEGAR.
WHITE WINE.
AND THEN SUGAR. WHISK,
BRING IT TO A BOIL,
TURN IT DOWN, LET IT SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE.
A LITTLE BIT
OF CANOLA OIL DOWN,
THROW DOWN OUR POT STICKERS.
I LOVE POT STICKERS.
YEAH, I DO, TOO.
I THINK IF I CAME BACK
IN ANOTHER LIFE,
MY MIDDLE NAME
MIGHT BE POT STICKER.
WE'LL LET THE BOTTOMS
GET A LITTLE CRISPY,
AND THEN WE'LL JUST GO AHEAD
AND HIT IT WITH WATER
AND COVER IT UP.
FROM START TO FINISH,
THEY TAKE ABOUT 10 MINUTES.
(whistles)
WE GO AHEAD AND TAKE
THE COVER OFF.
THOSE LOOK AWESOME.
BRING THESE OVER HERE.
SUPER NINJA
MOLTEN POT STICKERS.
THERE WE GO,
AND SESAME SEEDS ON TOP.
AND THIS IS OUR
DIPPING SAUCE?
YEP.
MMM. DYNO, BRO.
A LITTLE CRISP ON THE BOTTOM.
IT HOLDS TOGETHER WELL.
THE SAUCE ROCKS.
A LITTLE SWEET,
A LITTLE TANG. MMM.
BUT I THINK THE FACTOR
THAT I ENJOY THE MOST
IS THE FACT THAT
YOU MADE THE SKIN. MMM.
IT'S GOT GOOD TEXTURE.
MMM. THANK YOU.
THIS IS GREAT, MAN.
THANKS.
POT STICKERS.
NICE AND CRISPY,
WITH THE DELICIOUS SAUCE.
THEY'RE GREAT.
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
STARTING THAT
GORGONZOLA PENNE.
FAMILIAR, YET UNIQUE.
FRANK, WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA HAVE?
AWESOME ACROSS THE BOARD.
EVERYBODY FINDS SOMETHING
THEY LOVE.
THE BEST NEIGHBORHOOD
RESTAURANT IN SPOKANE.
THANK YOU.
BUT THAT'S WHAT WE SAY
ON TRIPLE "D" ALL THE TIME,
IS SLOW DOWN AND TAKE A LOOK
AROUND AT THESE LITTLE GEMS.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA
LOVE THIS PLACE. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
GOOD JOB.
UP NEXT...
ENFRIJOLADAS WITH AVOCADO.
WE'RE HEADING
TO PHILADELPHIA...
SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
FOR A TASTE...
MMM.
OF THE SOUTH...
CHICKEN CHILI
FRITO PIE.
AND MORE.
FRESH LATKES DOWN!
I'M HERE IN NORTHERN LIBERTIES,
PHILADELPHIA,
JUST NORTH OF THE OLD CITY--
YOU KNOW, WHERE THEY SIGNED
THE DECLARATION
OF INDEPENDENCE--
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S IN A BUILDING
THAT SOME PEOPLE SAY
WAS ONCE A PRODUCE MARKET--
SOME SAY A COFFIN SHOP,
SOME SAY A BANK,
SOME SAY
EVEN A MATTRESS FACTORY.
NOW REGARDLESS
OF WHAT IT WAS THEN,
NOW IT'S HOME
TO A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S SERVING UP A BLEND
OF--GET THIS--
JEWISH FOOD
AND SOUTHERN COMFORT FOOD.
THIS IS HONEY'S SIT 'N EAT.
(man) BRISKET TACOS UP!
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
MIXING THE SOUTHERN STUFF
OWNER JEB WOODY GREW UP ON...
FRITO PIE, COMIN' HOT.
WITH THE JEWISH CLASSICS...
BRISKET SANDWICH.
HIS LIFE PARTNER
BROUGHT TO THE TABLE...
FRESH LATKES DOWN.
THE CHEESY POTATO LATKE.
IT'S JUST AWESOME.
(woman) MATZO BALL SOUP.
DELICIOUS. IT'S A GREAT
PLACE TO GO.
AND A NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE.
FRITO PLATTER.
THE PLACE ACTUALLY MADE
THE NEIGHBORHOOD HIP.
DID IT REALLY?
YEAH.
JUST WHAT JEB WAS AFTER.
ENFRIJOLADAS WITH AVOCADO.
MADE A PLACE THAT
WE WANTED TO GO...
AND THIS--
AND HAS THE FOOD
THAT WE EAT.
LIKE THIS TOP SELLER.
THE CHICKEN CHILI
FRITO PIE.
THAT'S A SPIN ON HIS
CHILDHOOD FAVORITE.
IT'S AMAZING.
CHICKEN CHILI FRITO PIE.
ALL RIGHT.
RAW CHICKEN--
JUST GONNA BOIL IT.
NO SALT, NO PEPPER,
NO NADA?
NOTHIN'.
LET THIS JUST GO UNTIL
IT COOKS DOWN.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER.
DISCARD THE SKIN,
AND JUST PULL LITTLE PIECES.
I'VE SHREDDED A CHICKEN OR
6,000. DARK MEAT, WHITE MEAT?
WHOLE THING.
AND THEN WE START MAKING
OUR GUAJILLO PEPPER SAUCE.
CHECK THESE OUT.
GUAJILLO PEPPERS ARE DYNAMITE.
A LOT OF TIMES, YOU FIND 'EM
FOR ENCHILADA SAUCE.
BUST THAT OUT, TAKE THE STEM
OFF, SLICE 'EM OPEN,
GET THE SEEDS OUT.
THREE PBR's, YOU OWE ME.
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
THE SAUCE.
FOR THE CHICKEN?
FOR THE CHICKEN.
START WITH SOME GARLIC CHOPPED
IN A HOT PAN OF OIL.
ROAST IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
DRIED GUAJILLO PEPPERS.
THE PEPPERS I CUT UP.
CRUSHED TOMATOES,
CHICKEN STOCK, TOMATO PASTE,
AND STIR.
THAT'S FOR THE SAUCE.
WE FOLD IN THE PULLED CHICKEN
THAT WE JUST...
THE PULLED CHICKEN THAT WAS
BOILED IN JUST THE WATER.
THAT'S JUST GONNA REDUCE DOWN
UNTIL IT--
THE SAUCE BECOMES SORT OF
A COATING OVER THE CHICKEN.
OKAY.
AND THE SKINS OF THE PEPPERS
ARE CHOPPED DOWN FINE ENOUGH
THEY'LL KIND OF
JUST DISSOLVE.
FROM THIS,
WE MAKE OUR CHILI.
WITH A BASE
OF NINE VEGGIES AND SPICES.
FIRST ADD OIL. SWEAT DOWN
THESE ONIONS AND BELL PEPPERS.
I'M GONNA START ADDING
EVERYTHING ELSE.
CRUSHED TOMATOES,
CHICKEN STOCK,
SWEET PICKLED PEPPERS...
OH, A LITTLE PEPPADEW.
PINTO BEANS...
BLACK BEANS.
PICKLED JALAPEÑOS.
JALAPEÑO.
KETCHUP, A LITTLE
TOMATO PASTE.
WHY WOULDN'T YOU?
CRUSHED CUMIN SEED,
MILD CHILI POWDER,
GROUND CAYENNE PEPPER,
TOUCH OF DARK BROWN SUGAR.
JUST A TOUCH.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET THIS COOK?
ABOUT 12 MINUTES.
SO IT
KIND OF REDUCES DOWN
TILL IT'S GOT
THE VISCOSITY OF CHILI?
RIGHT.
WE HAVE OUR CHILI BASE.
WE HAVE CHICKEN COOKED IN
THE GUAJILLO PEPPER SAUCE--
JUST MIXING IT,
MAKING THE TWO IN ONE.
I LIKE WHERE IT'S GOING.
I WANT TO SEE WHEN
IT TURNS INTO A PIE.
NOW...
OH, WE DO HAVE
REAL FRITOS.
WE HAVE FRITOS.
(imitates chomping)
BRING MY CHILI TO THE PIE.
CRAZY.
ADD YELLOW CHEDDAR.
UP INTO THE SALAMANDER.
JUST MELTING THE CHEESE.
FINISH IT UP WITH A GARNISH
OF SCALLIONS.
THAT'S A BAR SNACK 101.
MMM.
I GET THE GUAJILLO
RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
RIGHT WHEN I GOT A BITE
OF THE CHICKEN.
IT'S A REAL FRESH CHILI.
GREAT TEXTURE, GREAT FLAVOR,
GREAT CRUNCH--I CAN
REALLY TASTE THE FRITO.
MMM. IT'S THE GUAJILLO
CHICKEN, DUDE.
REALLY TAKES IT
SOMEPLACE ELSE.
THAT'S NOT YOUR EVERYDAY
CHILI RIGHT THERE, FOLKS.
I'D ORDER THAT AGAIN
IN A HEARTBEAT.
CHICKEN CHILI FRITO PIE.
FRITOS--CLASSIC.
THAT CHICKEN--
A LITTLE TANG TO IT. OHH.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS AMAZING.
CORNED BEEF REUBEN,
SIDE ONION RINGS.
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE.
TWO LATKES ON THE FRYER.
REPRESENTATION OF AMERICA.
ENFRIJOLADAS.
MELTING POT OF A LOT
OF DIFFERENT CULTURES.
LIKE THEIR BRISKET.
THIS IS BUBBY'S RECIPE--
MY PARTNER'S GRANDMOTHER.
BUBBY IS YIDDISH
FOR GRANDMA.
BRISKET FRITO, COMIN' HOT.
STARTS
NORTHEASTERN JEWISH,
AND WE'RE ABOUT
TO TAKE IT SOUTHWEST.
JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S AWESOME.
BRISKET FRITO PLATTER.
NOT FRITO LIKE
"THE FRIED CHIP,"
BUT FRITO, AS IN,
SPANISH FOR "FRIED."
OKAY.
WHOLE BRISKET.
RAW CELERY, RAW ONIONS,
ROUGHLY CHOPPED CARROTS,
CHOPPED TOMATOES.
AND IT'S JUST
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL?
YEAH. POTATOES,
WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES.
FRESH BAY LEAVES,
FRESH THYME--UNPROCESSED.
MMM.
TOMATO PASTE--
AND THIS IS THE SECRET--
LIPTON ONION SOUP MIX.
THE OLD-SCHOOL
ONION SOUP MIX?
ONION SOUP MIX.
THAT'S HOW BUBBY
WOULD MAKE IT.
YEP. WATER ALMOST COVERING
THE WHOLE THING.
AND NOW THE LAST COMPONENT--
A LITTLE RED WINE.
STIR THESE INGREDIENTS TOGETHER,
COVER IT WITH FOIL.
AND HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
5 HOURS AT 350.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT.
ROASTED BRISKET,
READY TO SLICE.
COOLS DOWN, THE FAT
FLOATS TO THE TOP.
JUST GONNA SLICE IT UP.
CUT WITH THE GRAIN.
AND WE MOVE ON TO SAUTé.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT
SEAR UP.
RENDER DOWN
SOME OF THAT FAT.
GET SOME OF THAT FLAVOR
TRAPPED INSIDE.
A LITTLE BIT OF LIME JUICE.
RED ONIONS, SLICED.
GIVE IT A TOSS.
AND CHOPPED SCALLIONS.
I FEEL LIKE I'M GOING
A LITTLE TEX-MEX,
SOUTHWESTERN HERE.
AND THIS IS GONNA GO
RIGHT ON THE PLATE.
SO BIG OL' PIECES
OF BRISKET, TWICE COOKED,
GET A LITTLE FRITO--
A LITTLE CRUST ON THAT,
DEGLAZE IT
WITH THE LIME JUICE,
SOME NICE FRESH
RED ONION.
A LITTLE GARNISH
FOR COLOR.
DUDE, THIS IS SCREAMING
TORTILLA RIGHT NOW.
BUILD THE TORTILLA TOWER.
LIKE IT.
MMM. OUT OF BOUNDS.
DUDE, THIS IS DOING THE DANCE.
IT'S LIKE
DONNY AND MARIE OSMOND--
IT'S A LITTLE BIT COUNTRY
AND A LITTLE BIT ROCK 'N' ROLL.
RIGHT, YEAH, YEAH.
INCREDIBLY ENJOYABLE.
SIMPLE, YET FANTASTIC.
MMM. I'M GETTING AWAY FROM IT.
IT TASTES DELICIOUS.
REALLY TENDER.
PERFECTLY SPICED.
THIS IS BETTER
THAN BUBBY'S?
BETTER THAN BUBBY'S.
THE LATKES.
YOU KNOW YOU CAN BRING
THE WHOLE FAMILY HERE,
AND EVERYBODY'S
GONNA LEAVE HAPPY.
(woman) TASTES GOOD, HUH?
LOVE THE FOOD,
LOVE THE PLACE.
YOU COME, YOU SIT AND YOU EAT.
IT'S A SIT 'N EAT.
DO YOU HAVE THOSE
IN TEXAS?
NO, NO--I JUST--
YOU MADE UP SIT 'N EAT?
YEAH, I JUST CAME--
I'D BE GETTING TO THE TRADEMARK
OFFICE ON THAT ONE.
THANKS.
JEB, AWESOME PLACE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS, MAN.
NEXT STOP...
IT HITS THE SPOT
EVERY TIME.
WE'RE HEADING TO LOUISIANA...
CHARLES, HOW YOU DOING?
FOR SOME CLASSIC
CREOLE.
OYSTERS LA LUZIANNE.
THOSE ARE MONEY!
ALL RIGHT!
SO HERE I AM
IN BEAUTIFUL MANDEVILLE,
ON THE NORTH SHORE
OF LAKE PONTCHARTRAIN,
JUST A QUICK 25-MILE JAUNT
ACROSS THE CAUSEWAY
FROM NEW ORLEANS,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S GOT A NAME
THAT'S AS UNIQUE
AS THE CHEF WHO OWNS IT.
THIS IS
LOUIE & THE REDHEAD LADY.
I CAN DANCE.
AND THIS IS LOUIE...
HERE WE GO.
VOODOO BENEDICT.
CHARLES, HOW YOU DOING?
AND THIS IS THE REDHEAD LADY.
SO HE HAS HIS OWN
SPECIAL PANCAKES.
LOVE GINGER AND LOUIE.
NEW ORLEANS NATIVES
CHEF LOUIE FINNAN...
COMING AROUND.
AND HIS WIFE GINGER.
OKAY, I WILL. YOU KNOW HE'S BACK
THERE SLAVING IN THE KITCHEN.
THE OWNERS REALLY MAKE IT
AS WELL AS THE FOOD
AND THE FLAVORS.
RED BEANS AND RICE.
THIS IS REAL-DEAL
LOUISIANA?
YES, THIS IS AS GOOD
AS IT GETS.
I'VE BEEN IN THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS FOR ALMOST 40 YEARS.
OYSTERS LA LUZIANNE.
THAT'S FOUR DECADES
OF MAKING LOUISIANA
FAVORITES.
I'VE GOT OYSTER PO-BOY.
I LOVE THEIR
FRIED CATFISH.
CRAB CAKES ARE AWESOME.
THE OYSTERS.
OYSTERS IN LOUISIANA--
IT'S THE KEY, BUT FRIED?
IT'S THE BEST.
IN A GARLIC
AND BUTTER SAUCE
ON THE HALF SHELL--
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DIVINE.
NOW WHERE ARE THESE OYSTERS
COMING FROM?
THESE ARE LOUISIANA WATERS.
THE WATERS
RIGHT OUT HERE? OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA FRY
THESE OYSTERS FIRST.
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE DRY BATTER MIX.
SO A LITTLE FLOUR.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, PREPARE
YOURSELF FOR EXACT MEASUREMENTS.
EXACTLY. A LITTLE
CREAM MEAL, CORN FLOUR,
CRAB BOIL, CAJUN SPICES,
LEMON PEPPER.
GET OUTTA HERE.
I THINK WE MIGHT BE OFF
BY THAT MUCH.
NOW WE'RE ADDING THE OYSTERS
TO THE DREDGE.
THE JUICE THAT CAME OUT
WHEN THEY WERE SHUCKED
STAYS IN THERE.
RIGHT, THE FLAVORS
ARE TOO SUBTLE.
YOU DON'T WANNA PUT A WASH ON
IT, 'CAUSE IT'S GONNA CHANGE IT.
WHERE YOU GOIN'?
WE'RE GOING
TO THE FRYER.
WELL, COME ON THEN.
SO YOU'RE JUST GONNA
KIND OF SUBMERGE THEM.
THIS IS, UH, CAJUN TEMPURA.
THOSE ARE HOT AND FAST, OKAY.
WE'RE MAKING THE GARLIC AIOLI.
A LITTLE BUTTER.
A LITTLE GARLIC, PARSLEY,
AND A SHOT OF OLIVE OIL.
WE'LL PUT THESE IN HERE.
PLEASE.
NOW WE'RE HEADING THE OYSTERS
TO THE SHELLS.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS GOING.
YOU'RE GONNA LIKE THIS.
YEAH, I'M GONNA
LIKE THIS.
CHEESE, A LITTLE PARM,
A LITTLE ROMANO.
SWEETNESS OF THE PARM,
SHARPNESS OF THE ROMANO.
EXACTLY.
IN THE BROILER.
DO YOU HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
OR HOW DO YOU
GO ABOUT IT?
OH, NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
NO, NO, NO?
EVERYTHING THAT YOU NEED
IS THERE, BUDDY.
THOSE... ARE MONEY!
ALL RIGHT!
THESE ARE LIGHT,
GREAT FLAVOR.
SUPER FRESH SEAFOOD.
GARLIC'S COOKED PERFECTLY.
NICE CRUNCH.
THEY ARE MOIST IN THE MIDDLE.
THIS RIGHT HERE IS STILL
HIGHLIGHTING THE SEAFOOD,
JUST PUTTING A LITTLE BIT OF
CRUNCH-IFICATION ON THE OUTSIDE.
THANK YOU.
CRUNCH-IFICATION.
THAT'S A NEW WORD.
OYSTERS LA LUZIANNE.
ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
AND YOU'VE HAD OYSTERS
AROUND THIS AREA?
FROM FLORIDA TO NEW YORK,
AND BACK AGAIN.
AND THIS IS THE SPOT?
THIS IS IT.
ONE LITTLE SHRIMP,
TWO LITTLE SHRIMP,
AND ANOTHER SHRIMP.
LOUIE JUST FEEDS UP JOY.
ENGLISH MUFFINS
ON THE PLATE, DAD.
"ENGLISH MUFFINS
ON THE PLATE, DAD."
(both laughing)
IT'S NOT JUST THE FOOD.
IT'S THIS GREAT EXPERIENCE OF
LOUIE AND THE REDHEAD LADY.
THE BIG HEART.
WE'RE NOT FANCY,
WE'RE FAMILY.
WE'RE FAMILY, RIGHT.
ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
MY MOTHER WAS THE REDHEAD LADY
ORIGINALLY.
AND SOME OF THE FAVORITES HERE
STILL COME
FROM HER FAMILY COOKBOOK.
CRAB CAKE GOING DOWN!
LIKE THE SAUCE
ON THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC.
COMING WITH
THE GREEN TOMATOES.
DONE WITH A LOUIE'S TWIST.
WITH BEAUTIFUL,
BEAUTIFUL SHRIMP.
AND THAT SAUCE THAT HE PUTS
ON TOP--IT'S AMAZING.
OKAY.
GONNA BOIL SOME SHRIMP.
ADD IN THE WATER,
CRAB BOIL, CAJUN.
SO CRAB BOIL CAJUN SPICE.
WE'RE GONNA DO A LITTLE
HOT SAUCE IN HERE.
WE NEED A LITTLE ACID.
JUST GOTTA KEEP UP
WITH THIS GUY.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU
AHEAD OF EVERYBODY.
I'M USUALLY THE ONE
ROWING AND STEERING THE BOAT.
RIGHT NOW I'M JUST HOLDING
ONTO THE BACK ROPES.
DON'T FALL IN THE WATER.
ONIONS, LEMON.
NOW LOOK AT THOSE
BAD BOYS.
SWIMMING LAST NIGHT.
THESE ARE GONNA GO UNTIL
THEY JUST TURN OPAQUE?
YES.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THE BROTH
RIGHT NOW
THEY'RE KICKING OFF--
YUM!
SO WE SCOOP 'EM OUT
TO THE ICE BATH.
YOU ADD A LITTLE BIT OF BROTH,
SO AS THEY COOL DOWN,
THEY COOL DOWN
IN SOME OF THIS FLAVOR.
SO NOW WE'RE MAKING
A LITTLE REMOULADE.
MAKING A REMOULADE SAUCE.
WE PUT A LITTLE MAYONNAISE,
A LITTLE HORSERADISH.
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
A LITTLE LEMON JUICE,
A LITTLE WORCESTERSHIRE.
CREOLE MUSTARD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX IT.
THERE YOU GO, MY BROTHER.
THAT WITH THE SHRIMP
AND THE--
WHOO!
WE'RE OFF THE HOOK.
WE--WE ARE OFF THE HOOK.
AND NOW IT'S TIME TO MAKE
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES?
YES.
CUT A LITTLE TOMATO.
WE START OUR LITTLE DREDGE.
MILK, A LITTLE EGG WASH.
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
YOU'VE DONE THIS BEFORE?
NOT MY FIRST RODEO.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR FLOUR DREDGE.
GOT A LITTLE FLOUR.
SALT, AND THIS IS A LITTLE
ITALIAN DRESSING MIX.
ITALIAN DRESSING THAT YOU WOULD
ADD VINEGAR AND OIL TO--
EXACTLY.
A DRY DRESSING.
OKAY.
GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
AND THEN WE GOT--
WHAT'S THE MIXTURE BACK HERE?
THAT'S AN ITALIAN
BREADCRUMB MIX.
ADD TO THAT PARMESAN CHEESE
AND THE CAJUN SPICE.
SO THE WETNESS
OF THE TOMATO
ATTRACTS THE FLOUR...
RIGHT.
AND THE FLOUR ATTRACTS
THE EGG WASH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM
IN THE BREADCRUMBS.
NOW WE'RE FRYING
OUR GREEN TOMATOES.
BOILS RUNNING ABOUT?
375.
SO THESE JUST GO
UNTIL THEY BROWN UP.
YOU WANT TO HAVE 'EM
JUST MOIST--
JUST WARM IN THE CENTER.
A LITTLE GREENS,
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
ALL RIGHT, WE GOT
OUR LITTLE SHRIMP.
NOW THE PIèCE de RéSISTANCE--
THIS TIES EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
THERE WE GO.
BROTHER, THIS IS A SYMPOSIUM
OF FLAVOR.
DELICATE SHRIMP,
SUPER GREAT FLAVOR.
THAT IS FAR MORE REFINED THAN
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA GET.
THANK YOU.
YOU ARE THE MAN.
IT'S VERY, VERY GOOD,
VERY FRESH.
EAT 'EM BREAKFAST,
LUNCH, AND DINNER.
YEP, SHE SAID BREAKFAST.
LOUIE'S DOING IT
CREOLE STYLE...
I GOT A GRILLADES AND GRITS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
THIS IS A BREAKFAST
THAT EATS LIKE A DINNER.
WEL... (laughs)
WELCOME BACK TO TRIPLE "D."
WE'RE AT
LOUIE AND THE REDHEAD LADY
IN MANDEVILLE,
JUST OUTSIDE NEW ORLEANS,
AND THIS GUY
IS OUT OF CONTROL.
THAT'S HOW WE STAY IN LINE
DOWN HERE.
WE'RE MAKING BREAKFAST NOW.
THIS IS OUR
BREAKFAST PLACE,
AND LOUIE FIXES US
WHATEVER WE WANT.
BANANA FOSTER PANCAKES.
COME HERE ON SUNDAYS,
IT'S THE BEST BREAKFAST.
I GOT A GRILLADES AND GRITS.
GRITS AND GRILLADES--
IT'S ACTUALLY A VEAL PATTY
AND GRITS.
IT'S A TYPICAL
LOUISIANA BREAKFAST.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD,
AND IT'S WONDERFUL.
I'M A GRIT-EATING FOOL.
WE'RE STARTING WITH GRITS.
A LITTLE WATER,
BUTTER, SALT.
YOU BRING THE WATER TO A SIMMER
AND THEN ADD THE GRITS?
YES.
SO WE LET THESE WORK,
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA START
WORKING ON THE VEAL.
SO JUST A NICE LITTLE
TENDERIZING.
THEN--WHAT--HE--SAID...
(speaking gibberish)
ALL--THE--WAY--ALL--DAY--LONG...
OKAY, LET'S DO A LITTLE FLOUR,
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
PRECISE MEASUREMENT.
EXACTLY.
ITALIAN DRESSING, SALT.
YOU KNOW, IN NEW ORLEANS,
YOU NEVER LEAVE ANYTHING ALONE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE GOTTA SEASON EVERYTHING.
SO THERE'S
OUR LITTLE DREDGE.
A LITTLE, UH,
BUTTER-FLAVORED OIL.
BLACK IRON SKILLET.
PUT A LITTLE SEASONING.
STEAK SEASONING?
YES. NOW WE'RE GONNA START
OUR SAUCE.
A LITTLE BUTTER-FLAVORED OIL,
SOME JULIENNED ONIONS.
OKAY, THIN-SLICED
WHITE ONION.
YES, SIR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF...
BEEF STOCK
THAT YOU MAKE IN-HOUSE.
LET THAT SIT THERE AND COOK DOWN
WITH THOSE ONIONS,
SO IT REDUCES REAL NICE.
GARLIC.
I AIN'T AFRAID OF GARLIC.
DON'T BE.
PICKAPEPPA SAUCE.
OH, I LOVE PICKAPEPPA.
KIND OF A VINEGARY
STEAK SAUCE. WHAT DO YOU GOT?
A LITTLE SHERRY.
SO A REAL NICE TRADITIONAL OLD
STEAK SAUCE WE'RE MAKING HERE?
ABSOLUTELY.
NOW MAKE A LITTLE ROUX
TO THICKEN IT.
OKAY.
SOME FLOUR AND SOME
MELTED BUTTER. WHISK THAT.
STICKS RIGHT ON THERE.
THAT SAUCE IS GONNA
BE OUT OF BOUNDS.
PUTTING THE VEAL INTO
THE GRILLADES GRAVY.
NOW WE START TO ABSORB
SOME OF THAT GREAT AU JUS
INTO THE CRUST
OF THE VEAL CUTLET.
RIGHT.
NICE TIGHT GRITS.
YES, SIR.
DON'T HOLD BACK.
OH, YOU WANT SOME MORE?
DON'T HOLD BACK ON ME. MATTER
OF FACT, JUST FILL THAT UP.
WHAT?
OH, OH.
TALKIN' HUGE FLAVOR.
HUGE FLAVOR.
THIS IS A BREAKFAST
THAT EATS LIKE A DINNER.
I DON'T WANT
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
GRITS AND GRILLADES.
ONE OF MY
FAVORITE DISHES.
THE VEAL IS NICE
AND TENDER.
WONDERFUL SAUCE. IT HITS
THE SPOT EVERY TIME.
BROTHER, I GOTTA
TELL YOU SOMETHING,
THIS IS AN EXPERIENCE,
AND THEN SOME.
YOU GOTTA COME MEET THIS GUY.
IT IS OFF...
THE HOOK! HEY!
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
MY KIDS LOVE TO GO
TO Disneyland,
AND WE HAVE A GOOD TIME
WHEN WE GO THERE,
BUT THIS, TO ME,
IS LIKE MY Disneyland.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU'RE JUST A Disneyland
CHARACTER WITHOUT THE FUR.
OH, I GOT
THE EARS, THOUGH.