HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(imitating lightsaber)
PO'BOYS...
MMM. DYNAMITE SANDWICH.
PASTA...
MMM.
AND PORK...
WINNER WINNER, DUDE.
IN NEW ORLEANS...
IT'S NUMBER ONE.
THE PO'BOY SHOP...
LARGE FRENCH FRY PO'BOY.
CRANKIN' 'EM OUT...
BEN IS VERY CREATIVE.
22 DIFFERENT WAYS...
AND YOUR FAVORITE?
CHICKEN LIVER
AND COLESLAW.
AND, HEY, LOOK
WHO'S STOPPING BY...
RENOWNED CHEF EMERIL LAGASSE.
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
FANTASTIC.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE TO EAT.
THE LOCAL LANDMARK...
IT'S READY TO GO.
PAIRING PASTA WITH PORK...
MMM. OUT OF BOUNDS.
AND THEY'RE TAKING FRESH
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
GROW 'EM. PICK 'EM. IT DOESN'T
GET ANY FRESHER THAN THAT.
AND IN CHAMPLIN, MINNESOTA...
THEY DID IT RIGHT.
THE BARBECUE JOINT...
1 POUND SPARE WITH MASH.
TRIPLE "D" VIEWERS...
(woman) MEAT'S
REALLY TENDER, JUICY.
IT'S JUST WHAT
WE WERE LOOKING FOR.
JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
THE BEST BARBECUE I'VE EVER HAD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
IN ONE OF THE GREATEST
FOOD CITIES IN THE WORLD--
NEW ORLEANS--
TO CHECK OUT ONE OF THE MOST
ICONIC FOODS OF THE AREA,
THE SANDWICH KNOWN
AS THE PO'BOY.
AND I HEAR ONE OF THE JOINTS
JUST KNOCKING IT OUT OF THE PARK
IS MAHONY'S,
AND TO GET THAT FULL
NEW ORLEANS EXPERIENCE
AND GET THE REAL LOWDOWN
ON THE PO'BOY,
I INVITED MY FRIEND,
KIND OF LOCAL CUISINE,
RENOWNED CHEF EMERIL LAGASSE.
HEY, GUY.
HOW YOU DOING, BUD?
OH, I'M GREAT,
BROTHER.
PO'BOYS--THIS PLACE GOT IT?
MAHONY'S--THIS IS IT.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON, SIR?
WHAT'S GOING ON, GUYS?
HOW ARE YOU?
SO WE SHOW UP TO GET
THE PO'BOY RUNDOWN.
I HAD TO BRING THE KING
WITH ME, SO...
I UNDERSTAND.
NEW ORLEANS LEGEND RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE NEIGHBORS.
ALL RIGHT,
THERE'S REAL SPECIFICS ABOUT
MAKING A GREAT PO'BOY.
WHAT IS THAT?
WELL, I THINK
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE BREAD...
YOU GOT TO HAVE
THE BREAD.
AND I THINK IT'S ABOUT
THE QUALITY INGREDIENTS.
BREAD DOWN.
AND EMERIL SAYS
CHEF BENJAMIN WICKS...
SMALL COCHON.
IS DOIN' IT RIGHT.
THAT'S WHY THEY'RE MAHONY'S'--
HIGH-QUALITY PO'BOYS DONE RIGHT.
AND DONE 22 DIFFERENT WAYS.
CATFISH.
BEN IS VERY CREATIVE.
(Ben) LARGE
FRENCH FRY PO'BOY.
AND YOUR FAVORITE?
CHICKEN LIVER
AND COLESLAW.
AND COLESLAW?
MM-HMM.
AND ONE CALLED THE PEACEMAKER.
MAKING A PEACEMAKER.
FRIED OYSTERS, BACON,
AND CHEDDAR--IT'S AWESOME.
WHERE DID THE PEACEMAKER
GET ITS NAME?
SAY YOU'RE OUT TOO LATE
AT A SAINTS GAME.
RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE TO HAVE PEACE
WITH THE MISSUS.
SO YOU--
SO YOU BRING HOME
THE PEACEMAKER.
OKAY.
ALL I USE IS 2 PARTS CORNMEAL
AND 1 PART FLOUR
AND MY OYSTERS.
LOOK AT THAT. WE HAVE
GREAT SEAFOOD IN LOUISIANA.
THESE ARE LOCAL OYSTERS
FROM P&J RIGHT HERE,
AND WE JUST GOT 'EM IN
AS WELL.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE'RE BREADED UP.
I JUST SHOOK
THE EXCESS BREADING OFF.
AND THEN WE FRY 'EM
IN PEANUT OIL.
THEY COOK FOR MAYBE A MINUTE
UNTIL IT TURNS GOLDEN BROWN.
THEY'RE GETTING HAPPY
RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE GETTING HAPPY.
THIS IS IT RIGHT HERE.
LOOK AT HOW BEAUTIFUL
THAT IS.
A LITTLE SALT
AND THAT'S IT.
HERE'S YOUR
LEIDENHEIMER BREAD.
THE BREAD HERE
IN NEW ORLEANS.
YOU HAVE TO USE
LEIDENHEIMER BREAD.
LEIDENHEIMER'S.
SEE HOW LIGHT AND AIRY
THAT IS?
LIKE A PILLOW.
YOU JUST WANT TO LAY IN THERE
AND GO TO SLEEP...
MM-HMM.
COVERED WITH OYSTERS.
YOU ARE INSANE.
SO MAYO--IT HAS TO BE
BLUE PLATE MAYO...
THAT'S
THE LOCAL MAYONNAISE.
OH, YEAH.
THE LOCAL PICKLES,
CALLED CAJUN CHEF,
AND TOMATOES AND LETTUCE,
COUPLE OF SLICES OF BACON ON
HERE, CHEDDAR CHEESE.
OH, YEAH.
CHEESE AND SEAFOOD,
MATCH MADE IN HEAVEN.
LOOK AT THOSE OYSTERS.
GET AS MANY ON THERE
AS YOU CAN. SEE THAT?
I MEAN, THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
WATCH THIS.
(imitates explosion)
OH, YES.
ISN'T THAT GREAT?
DYNAMITE.
BECAUSE THE WAY IT WAS BATTERED
AND FAST AS YOU FLASH-FRIED IT,
IT DOESN'T TASTE OILY
BY ANY MEANS.
FRY RIGHT
OR DON'T FRY AT ALL.
THAT'S THE PERFECT BITE
RIGHT THERE.
SEE, THE MAYONNAISE
IS COMING OUT,
THE OYSTER, THE CHEESE,
THE TOMATO.
A LITTLE BIT
IN EVERY BITE.
EVEN WITH THE BACON, EVERYTHING
IN THERE, THE DOMINANT FLAVOR...
IS THE OYSTERS.
IS THE OYSTER.
ABSOLUTELY.
GUYS, I GOT A LITTLE GIG WITH
MY FOUNDATION THIS AFTERNOON.
DIG IT.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
THANK YOU, SIR.
I'LL SEE YOU ALWAYS.
THANKS, MAN.
SEE YOU, BABE.
NICE HAVING YA.
BYE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
DUDE, TRIPLE "D" SHOWS UP IN
YOUR HOUSE AND EMERIL LAGASSE.
YEAH!
ALL RIGHT, PEACEMAKER.
IF THERE'S GONNA BE WORLD PEACE
ON THIS EARTH,
BACON AND OYSTERS,
THAT'S GONNA DO IT.
LARGE PEACE.
NICE AND CRISP, ALL THIS GOOD
STUFF TOGETHER IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
I REALLY, REALLY LIKE IT.
SO DID THE FOLKS AT
THE NEW ORLEANS PO-BOY FEST.
WE WON
WITH THE PEACEMAKER,
AND WE WON
WITH THE FRIED CHICKEN LIVERS
AND CREOLE COLESLAW.
WAIT A SECOND.
YOU'VE WON TWICE?
TWO YEARS IN A ROW.
AND THIS YEAR'S CONTENDER...
A ROOT BEER GLAZED HAM.
YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT
TO PUT THOSE TASTES TOGETHER,
BUT IT JUST WORKS OUT.
WORK GREAT.
YOU CAN REALLY TASTE
THE ROOT BEER,
AND IT'S ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
WE START OUT
WITH ROOT BEER EXTRACT,
2 OUNCES OF WATER,
DARK BROWN SUGAR...
DARK BROWN SUGAR.
COUPLE OF CINNAMON STICKS.
WHILE THAT'S MELTING,
CUT THIS HAM IN HALF.
THIS IS A LOCAL
CHISESI'S HAM.
CHISESI.
EVERYBODY IN NEW ORLEANS,
THIS IS THE HAM THEY EAT.
TALKING ABOUT SCORING
THE HAM.
THAT WAY THAT ROOT BEER
CAN SOAK UP IN THE CRACKS.
JUST POUR IT ON TOP
OVER HERE.
THE HAM'S ALREADY COOKED
AND CURED,
SO THIS IS JUST
FORTIFYING THE FLAVOR.
EXACTLY.
POP THIS IN THE OVEN
AND BASTE IT EVERY TEN MINUTES.
WELL, THIS ENTIRE KITCHEN SMELLS
LIKE ROOT BEER RIGHT NOW.
AND THEN IN 40 MINUTES
WE WILL HAVE A BAKED HAM.
THERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THEY'VE COOLED DOWN.
I CUT AGAINST THE GRAIN.
I'M GONNA POP IT HERE
ON THE SLICER.
YOU GOT TO CUT IT
AS THIN AS POSSIBLE.
CHECK THAT. YOU CAN SEE
THE LIGHT THROUGH IT.
(laughs)
THAT IS SO GOOD.
SINCE WE LET THE HAM COOL,
I WANT TO REHEAT IT.
ALL THIS FOR A SANDWICH?
IT'S A PO'BOY.
LET ME GRAB THE BREAD.
THAT IS A 30-INCH LOAF.
(imitating lightsaber)
AND IT'S VERY FRAGILE.
WE'LL MAKE A 12-INCH HERE.
POP IT INTO THE OVEN FOR ABOUT
TEN SECONDS. BITE INTO IT.
TEN SECONDS?
THAT'S IT.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
MAYO, PICKLES, TOMATOES,
LETTUCE, AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
NOW THIS IS THE RESERVE GLAZE
THAT I SCRAPED OUT OF THE PAN.
THERE YOU GO.
AND JUST LAYER IT ON,
FOLD IT OVER,
CUT IT IN HALF,
AND THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT ALL THE JUICE.
MMM. DYNAMITE SANDWICH.
THE BREAD'S ROCK STAR.
THE PORTION'S HUGE.
THE INGREDIENTS ARE FRESH.
WHAT REALLY STANDS OUT IS
THIS CRAZY ROOT BEER GLAZE, MAN.
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
IT'S POTENT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M A LITTLE KID,
HAVING A ROOT BEER FLAVOR
IN MY MOUTH,
THEN TAKING A BITE
OF MY LUNCH. AWESOME.
HAM AND CHEESE.
CAN YOU REALLY TASTE
THE ROOT BEER IN IT?
INCREDIBLY SO, VERY SWEET,
DELICIOUS.
ROOT BEER HAM,
JUST CHISESI'S HAM.
SMALL HAM DOWN.
AND THAT'S LOCAL.
THAT'S NEW ORLEANS.
EXACTLY WHAT THIS LOCAL BOY
WAS AFTER.
(Ben) GRILLED SHRIMP,
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
PEOPLE GETTING BACK
TO THEIR ROOTS
AND EATING FOOD
WHERE IT'S FROM.
LIKE A SWEET POTATO PIE...
HERE WE GO, MOM,
YOUR SWEET POTATO CRUNCH PIE.
INSPIRED BY THE COOKING
HE GREW UP WITH.
EVERY THANKSGIVING
I WOULD MAKE THE CASSEROLE,
AND MY BOYS LOVED IT.
WHEN HE OPENED THE RESTAURANT,
HE SAYS, "I'M GONNA MAKE
A PIE OUT OF IT."
SWEET POTATO CRUNCH PIE.
YEP, SO WE START
WITH SWEET POTATOES IN THE OVEN.
ROAST THEM OFF
LIKE WE ROAST BEETS.
EXACTLY.
SO THOSE ARE COOLED.
I'M JUST GONNA PEEL
THE SKIN OFF.
BREAK 'EM ALL DOWN.
YEP. A LITTLE CINNAMON,
NUTMEG,
GOT TO HAVE SALT
AND SUGAR.
GONNA BE SOME
SWEET POTATOES.
A COUPLE EGGS AND...
HEAVY CREAM,
JUST A TOUCH.
AND THAT'S IT.
I'M JUST GONNA FOLD IT OVER.
SO IT'S NOT
MASHED SWEET POTATOES.
OH, NO. IT'S SUPER CHUNKY.
AND THAT'S THE FILLING
RIGHT THERE.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE TOPPING--
LOUISIANA PECANS, BROWN SUGAR...
FLOUR TO BIND.
BUTTER AND SALT,
AND THAT'S IT.
I'M GONNA MIX IT TOGETHER
BY HAND.
THIS IS KIND OF LIKE THE CRUMBLE
YOU GET ON TOP OF COFFEE CAKE.
MOST DEFINITELY.
SO LET'S MAKE THE CRUST.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR, SUGAR,
SOME CHILLED BUTTER.
SALT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT ZEST IN HERE
FROM THIS ORANGE.
IT REACTS WITH THE FAT
SO YOU DON'T HAVE THIS BUTTER
COATING YOUR TONGUE.
DIG IT.
THIS IS THE JUICE
AND WATER.
NOW MOST PEOPLE USE DOUGH
CUTTERS. I USE MY HANDS.
BUT YOU ARE TRAINED
LIKE A NINJA.
YOU WANT TO GO FAST, TOO.
SOON AS THE BUTTER MELTS,
YOU'RE GONNA LOSE
THIS FLAKY CRUST-NESS.
EXACTLY.
BOOM. SO HERE IT IS.
WRAP IT UP IN PLASTIC.
LET IT REST.
IN THE REFRIGERATOR.
OKAY, SO LET'S ROLL OUT
THE DOUGH AND BUILD THE PIE.
ALL RIGHT, BEAUTIFUL.
A LITTLE FLOUR.
I'M JUST GONNA ROLL IT OUT,
MAKE IT AS ROUND AS POSSIBLE.
RUB A LITTLE BUTTER
IN HERE.
GOT TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE GREASING.
ROLL IT UP ON THE PIN,
PREVENT IT FROM BREAKING.
PUT IT IN THE PIE SHELL.
CUT OFF THE EXCESS.
PUT HOLES
IN THE CRUST.
HELPS IT
FROM BUBBLING UP.
PUT THE SWEET POTATO FILLING
IN THERE.
AND HIT IT WITH THE TOPPING.
LOOKING GOOD.
THAT'S IT.
POP IT IN THE OVEN
HOW LONG?
45 MINUTES TO A HOUR AT 350.
(clicks tongue)
ONCE IT COMES OUT OF THE OVEN,
LET IT COOL OFF.
THERE WE GO.
HOW MUCH DOES
THIS THING WEIGH?
YOU HAVE TO CUT THROUGH
THE BARK FIRST.
PUT SOME MINI MARSHMALLOWS
ON IT.
WHOA.
PULL OUT THE SECRET WEAPON--
BLOWTORCH.
LOOK AT THAT, DUDE.
MAKE SURE YOU EAT
EVERYTHING IN THERE.
MMM. WOW. IT'S RICH
BUT NOT OVERLY SWEET.
NICE BITE OF THE PECANS.
THE MARSHMALLOWS ON TOP,
WITHOUT A DOUBT, QUINTESSENTIAL.
IT'S ALL
REAL DEAL HERE, MAN.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M GOING FOR.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE HITTING.
SWEET POTATO CRUNCH.
BEST PIE I'VE EVER HAD,
AND I MAKE SWEET POTATO PIE.
(Ben) THE SWEET POTATO PIE.
I LIKE THE ORANGE ZEST
IN THE CRUST.
WITH THE MARSHMALLOWS AND IT'S
LIKE A CRèME BRûLéE ON TOP.
IT'S DOWN HOME GOOD FOOD.
FRENCH FRY AND ROAST BEEF.
THERE'S NO OTHER PO'BOY
LIKE IT.
COLESLAW AND CHICKEN LIVER.
CREATIVE, QUALITY,
SCRATCH-MADE.
I WILL BE BACK.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
DEFINITELY.
UP NEXT...
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
CHICKEN PHYLLO, PLEASE.
WHERE MAKIN' IT FRESH...
A LOT OF HANDMADE STUFF.
MEETS A TRIP TO THE ROOF.
GROW 'EM, PICK 'EM,
WASH 'EM, AND SERVE 'EM.
RIGHT.
SO HERE WE ARE
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON.
NOW THIS DOWNTOWN AREA WAS
RENOVATED BACK IN THE MID '70s
WHEN THEY HAD THE WORLD'S FAIR.
THE LOCATION WE'RE GONNA VISIT
WAS HERE IN THAT ERA,
AND IT WAS A PHARMACY.
THEN IT TURNED INTO A PAWN SHOP,
AND NOW IT'S HOME TO A JOINT
THAT'S BAKING THEIR OWN BREAD,
MAKING FRESH PASTA, AND THEY
GOT A GARDEN ON THE ROOF.
THIS IS
HILLS' RESTAURANT & LOUNGE.
CHICKEN AND BRIE
AND PANCETTA.
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE ARE.
LEMON BASIL CASHEW CHICKEN,
TO DIE FOR.
PICK UP
ON A GUMBO WITH OKRA.
HE JUST HAS SUCH DIVERSITY.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
HE IS OWNER DAVE HILL
WHO OPENED THIS PLACE...
HERE WE ARE.
WITH HIS BROTHER STEVE
AND CREATED A MENU
INSPIRED BY THEIR CHILDHOOD.
(Dave) WE GREW UP OVERSEAS
IN SINGAPORE, HONG KONG,
LONDON, AND TEHRAN.
WE KIND OF APPRECIATED FOOD
AT AN EARLY AGE.
SO YOU'RE MAKING
AN ECLECTIC MIX OF FOOD,
MAKING AS MUCH OF IT
AS YOU CAN BY SCRATCH,
YOU MAKE THE PANCETTA.
YOU MAKE THE PASTA.
AND HE SMOKES
THE MONTEREY JACK CHEESE,
AND HE'S PUTTING HIS OWN
PULLED PORK ON A HOMEMADE BUN.
(woman) IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF EXTRA SPICE TO IT. MMM.
I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE WHAT
THAT IS, BUT IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHOA.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH A RUB FOR THE PORK BUTT--
BLACK PEPPER...
FRESH GROUND,
I LIKE THAT.
GRANULATED ONION,
GRANULATED GARLIC, TURMERIC,
OUR HOUSE SPICE
AND CHIPOTLE PEPPER,
CHINESE FIVE-SPICE...
(whispers) FIVE.
CUMIN, BROWN SUGAR,
AND FRESH GROUND COFFEE.
(normal voice) NICE.
AND THAT'S THE RUB FOR...
THE PORK BUTT.
SO WE GOT OUR RUB DONE.
SO WE'RE GONNA DO
THE BARBECUE SAUCE--
PINEAPPLE JUICE,
SOY SAUCE.
SO FAR WE GOT
TERIYAKI SAUCE.
WE GOT BALSAMIC VINEGAR,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR...
GOT TO HAVE THAT.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
AND KECAP MANIS, WHICH IS
A SWEET MALAYSIAN SOY SAUCE.
A CROSS BETWEEN SOY SAUCE
AND MOLASSES.
YEAH.
SO WE ADD OUR KETCHUP
AND TOMATO PURéE,
BLACK PEPPER...
(whistles)
HOUSE SPICE, FIVE-SPICE,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
AND OUR BROWN SUGAR,
AND THEN MIX IT UP.
WOW, LOOK AT THAT
HANDY-DANDY ATTACHMENT.
SO THIS HASN'T HAD A CHANCE
TO KIND OF WORK TOGETHER.
RIGHT.
(whistles)
A LOT GOING ON THERE.
YEAH.
IT HAS MORE POLYNESIAN FLAIR
TO IT THAN I ANTICIPATED.
IT GOES REALLY WELL
WITH THE RUB.
TAKE A NICE AMPLE AMOUNT
OF THIS STUFF.
THAT HEAVY, HUH?
YEAH. RUB THE PORK BUTT.
WE'LL COVER THEM.
AND THAT SETS ALL NIGHT
IN THE WALK-IN.
IT'S GOT A NICE COLOR
TO IT.
AND THEN WE SEAR UP
THESE BABIES.
AND THAT GREAT BARK,
THAT'S WAY DOWN IN THERE.
MARK IT OFF.
PRETTY WELL, YEAH.
BACK IN THE PAN, THROW IN
OUR APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
WHITE WINE...
WHOA.
AND OUR SOY SAUCE,
AND WE'RE ABOUT HALFWAY.
WRAP IT IN ALUMINUM FOIL.
THEN GO TO THE OVEN.
AT WHAT TEMP?
START IT AT 400,
TURN IT DOWN TO 300.
IT'S GONNA COOK
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS.
OKAY. WOW.
COOLED DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
YOU CAN SMELL
THE ASIAN FLAVOR TO IT.
LOOK AT THE WAY
IT JUST SHREDS RIGHT APART.
THAT'S GREAT,
NICE BALANCE...
THANKS.
REALLY NICE BALANCE.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU. STEP AWAY
FROM MY PORK WITH NICE BALANCE.
GO NOW. MOVE.
(laughs)
THIS STUFF'S GREAT. MMM.
THROW THE MEAT IN THE PAN.
THEN ADD OUR SAUCE.
GET THAT NICE AND HOT.
NICE LITTLE BIT
OF THE BARK IN THERE,
HEATING UP, PULLING APART.
SO FOR EACH ORDER
YOU MAKE IT LIKE THIS?
YOU'RE NOT HOLDING THIS
OUT ON THE LINE.
NO, NO.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA POUR IT
OUT OF THE PAN ONTO THE...
HANDMADE BUN, THERE YOU GO.
(whistles)
THAT'S A HEAP-A HONK
AND A SLAB-A SLICE-A JUNK-A.
(laughs)
LOOK AT THAT--
ASIAN PORK SLIDER.
DON'T KNOW WHY I
DIDN'T THINK THIS UP.
WINNER WINNER, DUDE. WOW. I'M
GETTING FLAVORS FROM EVERYWHERE.
A LITTLE SWEET, I GET THE SPICE,
THE OVERTONES OF SOY SAUCE.
YOU'RE CAPTAIN COMPLEXITY.
THE PORK IS SUPER JUICY.
THE BREAD'S FANTASTIC.
(mumbling)
THAT'S WHAT
MOST PEOPLE SAY.
REALLY?
YEAH.
SO I'M NOT THE FIRST ONE?
NO.
(Steve) PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
(woman) BARBECUE SAUCE
IS THE BEST.
THIS PULLED PORK
IS EXCELLENT.
MORE TENDER THAN I THOUGHT PORK
WOULD EVER BE. IT'S PERFECT.
EVERY TIME I'VE BEEN HERE,
THE FOOD HAS BEEN EXCELLENT.
DINNER IS SERVED.
A LOT OF FRESH
HANDMADE STUFF.
AND FRESH HAND-PICKED STUFF
ON THE ROOF.
GROW 'EM, PICK 'EM,
WASH 'EM, AND SERVE 'EM.
RIGHT.
IT DOESN'T GET
ANY FRESHER THAN THAT.
(Dave) PASTA'S GOING IN.
IS THAT THE ATTITUDE AROUND
HERE, THAT IF YOU CAN MAKE IT,
YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
EVEN THIS...
WORKING ON PANCETTA.
YOU KNOW, THAT
INCREDIBLE ITALIAN BACON,
DAVE'S MAKING THAT, TOO...
(Dave) PASTA GOING IN.
AND PAIRING IT
WITH HOMEMADE PASTA.
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
MAKING SOME PANCETTA, BUDDY.
ARE YOU READY?
OH, DUDE,
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW.
WE'RE MAKING THE CURE
FOR THE PORK BELLY--
BAY LEAVES, JUNIPER BERRIES,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
BROWN SUGAR, ALLSPICE, SALT,
AND A LITTLE PINK SALT.
NITRATE STABILIZER.
RIGHT.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
SO WE'RE GONNA DRY-RUB THIS
AND JUST LET IT SET?
PUT IT IN A PLASTIC BAG.
SQUEEZE THE AIR OUT.
LOCK IT UP.
IT'S JUST GONNA START
PULLING THE MOISTURE OUT.
EXACTLY.
THE PANCETTA GOES IN
THE COOLER FOR TEN DAYS.
IT'LL START GETTING
A LITTLE FIRM.
TAKE IT TO THE SINK
AND RINSE IT OFF. BLOT IT DRY.
AND NOW WE'RE GETTING READY
TO WRAP AND ROLL.
GIVE IT A GOOD,
TIGHT ROLL.
LOOK AT HOW STIFF
IT IS.
YEAH.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger) COME
ON, YOU CAN DO IT. WORK IT OUT.
(normal voice)
THERE YOU ARE.
SEASON THE OUTSIDE WITH
WHITE PEPPER AND WRAP IT.
TIE A LITTLE PLASTIC STRAP
TO IT,
THAT'LL HANG IN
THE WALK-IN.
FOR TWO WEEKS.
YEAH.
SO YOU JUST HAVE THEM
PERPETUALLY GOING IN THERE.
YEP. MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S FIRMED UP NICE.
NICE AND FIRM.
SLICE SOME OFF.
LOOK AT THAT.
I KNOW. I FEEL IT, TOO.
GET A NICE DICE.
GO TO THE PAN.
CLARIFIED BUTTER JUST TO GET
THAT BACON STARTING TO RENDER.
START TO WORK
THAT FAT OUT.
ONCE THE BACON'S GOT A LITTLE
CRISPY, ADD SOME GARLIC.
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME WHITE WINE.
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE GOING
WITH THIS.
LET THAT REDUCE FOR A MINUTE.
THEN YOU ADD SOME HEAVY CREAM.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE PASTA,
AND WE'LL COOK IT
THE REST OF THE WAY.
WE'LL ADD A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT,
OUR ROOFTOP HERB BLEND--
BASIL, SAGE, PARSLEY.
ROOFTOP HERB BLEND--
NOT MANY PEOPLE
GET TO SAY THAT LINE.
AND A LITTLE
PARMESAN CHEESE.
TIGHTEN IT UP A BIT.
THEN WE'RE READY TO PLATE.
GARNISH IT WITH SOME MORE
OF THE ROOFTOP HERBS,
SOME CLOVER SPROUTS, CARROTS,
SOME JULIENNE BEETS,
A LITTLE MORE CHEESE...
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
AND A BASIL LEAF,
AND THERE YOU GO.
BEAUTIFUL.
MMM. OUT OF BOUNDS.
BROTHER, THAT PANCETTA--
I'VE SPENT SOME TIME IN ITALY.
I'VE HAD
SOME REALLY GOOD PANCETTA.
BUT I GOT TELL
YOU SOMETHING, BUDDY,
THIS COULD GO UP
AGAINST ANYBODY.
IT'S DELICIOUS. THE PASTA'S
FANTASTIC, REAL NICE BITE TO IT.
IT'S CREAMY. MMM.
THIS IS JUST HITTING THE MARK.
AWESOME JOB. MMM.
THANK YOU.
PASTA WITH PANCETTA.
(man) IT'S SO DELICIOUS.
PANCETTA JUST ADDS A WHOLE NEW
ELEMENT TO THE DISH.
HERE YOU GO.
(man) VERY ORIGINAL.
IT'S ONE OF THE GREAT THINGS
ABOUT THIS PLACE.
YOU'RE GONNA FIND
UNIQUE THINGS HERE.
LIKE ONE OF THESE.
ELK BURGER UP.
YEP, ELK.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND
SOMETHING LIKE THIS
AT THE LOCAL BURGER JOINT.
THAT'S NOT A TYPICAL BURGER
RIGHT THERE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM. IT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
READY TO GO.
WE'RE BACK AT THE HILLS'
RESTAURANT & LOUNGE
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
PASTA COMING UP HERE.
WHERE OWNER DAVE HILL...
HERE WE GO.
AND HIS BROTHER STEVE
ARE SERVING UP
ALL KINDS
OF SCRATCH-MADE FAVORITES...
MMM.
WITH A TWIST.
LEMON BASIL CASHEW CHICKEN--
THAT'S MY FAVORITE ONE.
PULLED PORK UP.
IT HAS ITS OWN LITTLE
UNIQUE FLAVOR TO IT.
(Steve) BURGER FOR YOU.
EVEN BURGERS.
ALL RIGHT,
HERE'S YOUR ELK BURGER.
YEP, ELK.
(man) YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND
SOMETHING LIKE THIS
AT THE LOCAL BURGER JOINT
OR ANYWHERE ELSE IN TOWN.
AND THEY'RE SO POPULAR,
THEY'RE CRANKING OUT
MORE THAN 200 A WEEK.
YEAH.
TODAY, IT'S LINE COOK
KATIE GARRETT'S TURN.
ELK BURGER UP.
CUT THE ELK.
IN MANAGEABLE SLICES
YOU CAN DROP RIGHT IN
AND GRIND IT THROUGH.
YOU GUYS GET FRESH ELK IN
LIKE THIS ALL THE TIME?
WE DO.
A LITTLE BONELESS PORK BUTT.
MM-HMM. GIVES IT
A BETTER FLAVOR.
YOU NEED THE FAT,
'CAUSE ELK IS SUPER, SUPER LEAN.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA FIND IT.
FIRE IT UP.
THROW A COUPLE PIECES
UP HERE.
WOULD YOU LIKE
YOUR, UH...
YES, PLEASE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW...
WHOA. THIS IS LIKE
A CHILI GRIND NOW.
SO YOU JUST KEEP
RUNNING IT THROUGH.
THEN ONCE WE GET
ALL THE CHILI GRIND DONE,
THEN WE DO THE BURGER GRIND.
THE DARK IS THE ELK,
AND THE LIGHT IS THE PORK.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MUSTARD SAUCE ON THE STOVE.
RIGHT.
GOT IT.
LIGHT AND DARK BEER,
ADD THE MUSTARD, WHOLE SEEDS.
OUR LIGHT
AND OUR DARK SEEDS.
MARINATE OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE STRAIN THE SEEDS OUT.
THE SEEDS GO INTO THE BLENDER
AND THEN ARE
PARTIALLY GROUND UP.
OKAY.
WE GOT SOME WHOLE SEEDS
IN THERE STILL.
ALL OF THIS IS JUST GOING
FOR A MUSTARD SAUCE
THAT'S GOING ON THE BURGER?
ALL OF THIS IS FOR MUSTARD
FOR THE ELK BURGER.
ALL RIGHT.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
WE'VE GOT A DARK BEER,
PALE BEER.
AND WE'RE DOING THIS
IN A DOUBLE BOILER.
SO IT DOESN'T SCORCH.
OKAY.
ALLSPICE, SALT,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
DRIED MUSTARD.
OH, BROWN SUGAR.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS.
TURMERIC.
GREAT COLOR OUT OF THAT.
HORSERADISH GIVES IT
A LITTLE KICK.
AS MUSTARD DOESN'T HAVE
A KICK OF ITS OWN,
YOU NEED HORSERADISH.
WE'VE GOT GARLIC AND HONEY
FOR A LITTLE MORE SWEETNESS.
OOH, IT SMELLS LIKE
LAVENDER HONEY. CRAZY.
AND MALT VINEGAR.
(whistles)
NOW WE ADD THE MUSTARD.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
STIR.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIMMER?
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
ALL THAT FOR THE ELK BURGER.
GOT TO LOVE IT.
WE'RE READY
TO MAKE THE BURGER.
WITH OUR GRILL SPICE--
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION...
WHITE PEPPER.
GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
I LIKE IT.
WE'RE GONNA FORM OUR BURGER
WITH THE LID
TO MAKE IT NICE AND ROUND.
THROW ON A LOT OF THIS GRILL
SPICE BECAUSE IT DOESN'T GET
ANY SEASON IN THE MEAT,
REALLY NICE FLAVOR.
AND THERE WE GO.
FLIP THE BURGER. THEN WE ADD
OUR MUSHROOMS, A LITTLE SWISS.
ADD SOME EXTRA HEAT,
MELT IT REAL FAST.
WOW. EFFECTIVE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS ON?
ONE OF THE HOUSE-MADE BUNS.
PUT ON SOME LETTUCE,
TOMATO, AND ONION.
SO I'M GONNA PUT ON SOME OF THIS
BEER MUSTARD SAUCE THAT WE MADE.
HOLY MOLY.
THAT'S A HEALTHY PORTION.
AND THERE YOU GO.
NO MAYO.
NO, JUST OUR MUSTARD.
AND YOU MADE THE CHIPS ALSO.
YEP.
OKAY, SO HERE'S
THE BIG BURGER.
(laughs)
YEAH.
MMM. GREAT BURGER.
I THINK PEOPLE THINK,
OH, ELK, IT'S GAMY.
THIS RIGHT HERE
IS GROUND PERFECTLY.
NICE AND LEAN,
THE FAT OF THE PORK
REALLY HELPS BALANCE IT OUT.
GREAT TEXTURE. THAT'S NOT
A TYPICAL BURGER RIGHT THERE.
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF
THE MUSTARD. LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S GOT A LOT
OF COMPLEXITIES TO IT.
I WANT A BOTTLE OF IT. MMM.
I WOULD SERIOUSLY SIT HERE
AND EAT THE WHOLE THING,
BUT THEN YOU WOULD HAVE TO PROP
ME UP AND PUT ME IN MY CAR
AND PUT A BRICK ON THE...
NICE JOB. WELL DONE.
THANK YOU.
WE GOT THE ELK BURGER.
REALLY FLAVORFUL.
THE WHOLE THING'S GREAT.
COOKED JUST RIGHT SO YOU GET
THAT LEAN TASTE BUT STILL JUICY.
(man) THE MUSTARD SAUCE HAS GOT
A REAL GOOD SPICY TASTE
WITH TEXTURE AND ALL THAT IN IT.
IT WAS UNIQUE.
(Dave) WORKING ON TWO PASTAS.
IT'S FUN TO COME TO A RESTAURANT
THAT DOES SO MANY THINGS...
HANDMADE FETTUCCINE.
FRESH AND HOMEMADE.
OKAY, LOOKING GOOD.
FANTASTIC.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE TO EAT.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
WE'VE CRUISED AROUND THE COUNTRY
AND LOOKED FOR GREAT PLACES.
THE FOOD AND THE ATTITUDE
IS EXACTLY WHAT WE'RE INTO,
SO CONGRATULATIONS.
HEY, THANKS A LOT.
THANKS A LOT FOR HAVING US.
APPRECIATE IT.
LEARNED SOME
GOOD STUFF TODAY.
HEY, THANKS, GUY.
NEXT STOP...
HALF A RACK OF BACK.
WE'RE HEADING TO MINNESOTA...
1/3 POUND BRISKET.
WHERE IT'S YOUR TURN...
HERE'S YOUR BRISKET.
TO 'CUE IT UP.
I LOVE THE BARBECUE
AT Q FANATIC.
YOU KNOW, I LOVE HEARING FROM
FOLKS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
WHO ARE DOING WHAT I DO,
AND THAT'S SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND
AND FIND THEIR FAVORITE
LITTLE JOINTS
LIKE A BUNCH OF VIEWERS
WHO'VE BEEN SLOWING DOWN
FOR A PLACE
JUST OUTSIDE OF MINNEAPOLIS
IN CHAMPLIN, MINNESOTA,
AND HERE'S WHAT
THEY WANT ME TO KNOW
ABOUT Q FANATIC BBQ AND GRILL.
I E-MAILED YOU BECAUSE I REALLY
THOUGHT YOU SHOULD COME HERE.
AND SHE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE.
I LOVE THE BARBECUE
AT Q FANATIC.
HERE'S YOUR
BRISKET SANDWICH.
THERE'S A LOT
OF GOOD FOOD HERE.
BEEF, CHICKEN, PORK.
EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
IT'S A FRIENDLY
LOCAL RESTAURANT...
HOW YOU GUYS DOING?
WITH FABULOUS BARBECUE.
AND A CLASSICALLY TRAINED
CHEF...
I'VE GOT 2 POUNDS.
CHARLIE JOHNSON.
(Charlie) LEARNED MORE
OF A CUTTING-EDGE CUISINE
TO MAKE THE BEST BARBECUE
I COULD IN THE MARKET.
1/3 POUND BRISKET.
BRISKET'S MY FAVORITE,
AND THIS IS THE BEST I'VE HAD.
THANK YOU.
(woman) THE MEAT'S
REALLY TENDER, JUICY.
IT'S JUST WHAT
WE WERE LOOKING FOR.
(woman) PULLED PORK
WITH APPLE SAUCE.
AND YOU GUYS WANTED ME TO KNOW
THIS IS WHERE THE LOCALS GO.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CAN TELL THAT THEY MAKE
ALL OF THEIR FOOD FROM SCRATCH.
THEY DID IT RIGHT.
GREAT FLAVOR IN THE MEAT.
AND THEY SAY
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE SMOKE.
IT DOES HAVE
A SMOKY FLAVOR TO IT.
THE SMOKE
IS COMING FROM THE MEAT.
AND WHERE THERE'S SMOKE,
THERE'S FIRE.
(Charlie) I DECIDED
TO GIVE HICKORY A TRY.
IT SEEMS TO GIVE A NICE FLAVOR,
AND IT'S WORKING REALLY WELL.
MY BIG CUTS OF MEAT,
I COOK IN PANS
TO TRY TO RETAIN THE MOISTURE.
(man) HERE'S
THE BEEF BRISKET.
I USED THAT JUICE
TO REHEAT THE MEAT IN,
USING ITS OWN NATURAL GOODNESS
TO KEEP IT TENDER AND MOIST.
THE MEAT
IS SO PERFECTLY PREPARED.
(woman) THE SMOKY FLAVOR COMES
THROUGH ALL THE DIFFERENT MEATS.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
(woman) RIB TIP SANDWICH.
THAT'S HOW YOU CAN TELL THAT
IT'S GOOD, 'CAUSE IT'S GONE.
HALF A RACK OF BACK.
HE CERTAINLY KNOWS HIS BARBECUE.
IT'S VERY, VERY GOOD.
1 POUND SPARE WITH MASH.
AND IT'S ALL DONE CHARLIE'S WAY
WITH INSPIRATION FROM A COUPLE
OF CAPITALS OF AMERICAN 'CUE.
(Charlie) I DEVELOPED MY RUB
BASED ON A MEMPHIS-STYLE RUB.
WE HAVE EIGHT SAUCES,
FIVE DIFFERENT ONES IN
THE KANSAS CITY STYLE ALONE.
NOW ALL YOU GUYS
HAVE YOUR FAVORITES...
I'M READY FOR THE RIBS.
BUT ACCORDING TO CHARLIE,
THERE IS A CLEAR WINNER.
OUR BEST-SELLING SAUCE
IS THE ESPRESSO.
TANGY WITH A LITTLE SPICE IN IT.
YEP, HE'S PUTTING ESPRESSO
IN HIS TAKE ON
A KANSAS CITY-STYLE SAUCE...
DISSOLVE THE BROWN SUGAR.
WITH A LITTLE SWEET...
KETCHUP, BLACKSTRAP MOLASSES...
AND A LITTLE HEAT...
GRILL OFF FRESH JALAPEÑOS.
AND THE KICKER...
ESPRESSO.
THAT GREAT BIG SHOT OF JOE.
EXTRA STRONG.
AND THEN BLEND IT.
THAT SAUCE IS JUST PHENOMENAL.
IT'S A GREAT FINISH.
ALL RIGHT.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
BRISKET AND BEANS.
THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
AT THE TOP OF MY LIST.
AND A FEW OTHERS, TOO.
(woman) THE BEST BARBECUE
I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU GOT TO COME HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
GOSH, THIS GUY IS CRAZY.
(Italian accent)
YES, COME ON.
(Italian accent) THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE DOING IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S--IT'S EMILIO AND GUS.