HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LET'S GO THIS WAY.
PUB GRUB...
COUPLE TACOS FOR YOU.
AND MORE.
TOFU?
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA.
THEIR FOOD IS TOP-NOTCH.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD PUB...
HERE YOU ARE, LADIES.
CRANKING OUT
A VIETNAMESE CLASSIC...
BAHN MI.
OUT OF CONTROL.
AND PUT THEIR OWN SPIN
ON PIZZA.
NO CHEESE
AND NO SAUCE, MMM.
SMOKIN' THE SLAW,
REALLY GOOD.
IN WASHINGTON, D.C...
PORK AND CHEESE PUPUSA
PLATTER READY.
THE LOCAL JOINT...
WASHINGTON'S
BEST-KEPT SECRET.
SERVIN' UP TOTALLY...
TOTALLY.
AUTHENTIC
SALVADORAN FAVORITES.
THIS IS ONE OF THE TASTIEST
TAMALES. RIDICULOUS.
AND IN PHILADELPHIA...
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
THE 1920s BAR...
ONE 90 MINUTE FOR YOU.
DOING BAR FOOD...
PORK RILLONS WATERMELON SALAD.
WITH ATTITUDE AND...
SMOKED COCONUT CLUB.
CALLIN' ALL VEGETARIANS...
I KNOW, MOM.
I'M EATING TOFU.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I THINK BY NOW
MOST PEOPLE ARE AWARE
THAT I'M FROM CALIFORNIA
AND VERY PROUD TO BE.
NOW WHEN I HEAR THERE'S A JOINT
CLOSE TO THE STATE CAPITAL
HERE IN SACRAMENTO
THAT'S ROCKIN' OUT
HANDMADE GASTRO PUB FOOD,
AND THEY GET THEIR NAME
FROM THE GOLDEN STATE
AND THE BEAR ON ITS FLAG, WELL,
YOU KNOW I GOT TO CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS THE GOLDEN BEAR.
THESE TACOS
ARE READY TO SELL.
(man) I NEED A RUNNER!
THEIR FOOD IS TOP-NOTCH.
PLATING UP THE TACOS.
I'M HAVING THE CHICKEN TACOS.
I LOVE THEM.
I GOT A JUICY LUCY.
GREAT FOOD, GREAT FRIENDS.
IT'S ALL
NEIGHBORHOOD, MAN.
THAT'S WHAT
THE ATTITUDE WAS.
LOCAL.
OH, YEAH.
OPENED BY A COUPLE
OF LOCAL GUYS...
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
COLLEGE BUDDIES
KIMIO BAZETT...
DUCK CONFIT CLUB.
AND JON MODROW...
ENJOYING YOUR FOOD, GUYS?
ALWAYS.
WHERE FRIENDS
GET TOGETHER.
FOR DRINKS AND BAR BASICS...
HERE YOU ARE, LADIES.
TILL THEY BROUGHT IN
CHEF BILLY ZOELLIN...
BACON REUBEN.
TO TURN THE BAR MENU
ON ITS EAR.
PROSCIUTTO AND PEACH PANINI.
SO HE JUST TAKES EVERYTHING
AND JUST DOES IT THE BILLY WAY.
OH, YEAH.
YOUR BASIC REUBEN...
NO PASTRAMI.
IT'S ALL BACON, KIND OF CRAZY.
OR A CLUB SANDWICH.
BACON AND DUCK, VERY RICH,
BUT I LOVE IT REAL BAD.
AND HOW ABOUT A PIZZA?
NO SAUCE, NO CHEESE.
(man) HERE COMES THE SLAW.
IT'S MY FAVORITE ITEM
ON THE MENU.
IT'S OUR TAKE
ON A CLASSIC PICNIC SANDWICH,
SAUSAGE AND SLAW.
SMOKED SLAW--I'VE HEARD ABOUT
IT. SO WHAT DO YOU GOT?
WE START WITH SOME
HICKORY CHIPS, ROAST PAN,
ICE, PLASTIC WRAP,
SHREDDED SAVOY.
SO WE DON'T WANT TO COOK
THE CABBAGE.
EXACTLY.
JUST GONNA THROW SOME FLAVOR
TO IT WITH THE SMOKE.
YEAH.
PUT THAT ON TOP
OF OUR WOOD CHIPS.
THIS IS A FIRST.
COVER IT WITH TINFOIL.
HOW LONG YOU GONNA PUT IT
ON THE SMOKE?
FOUR MINUTES.
SO THE SLAW
IS PERFUMED WITH SMOKE.
CABBAGE GOES STRAIGHT IN.
OKAY.
HOUSE-MADE AIOLI, WHOLE-GRAIN
MUSTARD, APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR,
GRATED ONION.
NOW WE JUST GET THIS GOOD
AND MIXED, LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
(laughs) THAT CHANGES
MY WHOLE ATTITUDE ABOUT SLAW.
SO HOLD THIS COLD?
YEP.
ALL RIGHT.
TO MAKE THE SAUSAGE,
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME FRESHLY CHOPPED
GARLIC, CHOPPED ONION,
FRESH OREGANO,
FRESH CHOPPED PARSLEY.
ITALIAN?
OF COURSE. TOASTED GROUND
FENNEL, CHILI FLAKES,
LITTLE RED WINE,
RED WINE VINEGAR...
LITTLE BITE.
LITTLE SALT...
FRESH GROUND PEPPER
ONLY WAY TO GO.
DRIED OREGANO, LITTLE SUGAR.
THERE WE GO, BOOM.
WE'LL WHISK THIS UP.
OKAY.
SO WE GOT LOCAL
FRESH PORK.
CAN'T BEAT IT.
WE'LL GET THIS ALL GOOD
AND MIXED.
THIS IS GONNA REST UP
FOR AT LEAST 24 HOURS.
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT. NOW WE'RE GONNA
WORK ON THE ONIONS?
YEP.
SO SUPER-THIN SLICED
RED ONIONS.
LOW TEMPERATURE.
HIT IT WITH SOME SALT RIGHT OFF
THE BAT, DRAW OUT THE MOISTURE.
IT'S BEEN ABOUT 20, 25 MINUTES.
SO OUR ONIONS BREAK DOWN WELL.
I TAKE A LITTLE BALSAMIC,
REDUCE THIS DOWN...
EVEN MORE.
YEAH.
AND WHAT ARE THESE
GOING FOR?
RED ONION MARMALADE.
IN A SEPARATE PAN,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME CARAMEL.
NOW THAT GOES IN?
YES. WE ADD THAT
INTO OUR ONIONS.
I LIKE IT A LOT.
SEASON THIS
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
LAY IT OUT TO COOL.
AND THEN THAT'LL BE
THE BEGINNING OF THE TOPPING...
FOR OUR SMOKED SLAW
AND SAUSAGE PIZZA.
OKAY.
YEP.
SO THE MEAT'S HAD 24 HOURS
TO MARINATE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA RENDER
SOME OFF.
GOT TO GO WITH SMALL BATCHES.
YOU WANT THIS TO CLUMP UP
A LITTLE BIT, RENDER SOME OF
THE FAT, SO IT DOESN'T STICK.
YEAH.
BROWN THAT OFF.
BROWN THIS UP.
GREAT. NOW WE'RE READY
TO START MAKING THE PIZZA.
THAT'S IT.
STRETCH IT OUT TO ORDER.
SO TAKE THAT.
THE DOUGH GOES IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
PULL THE SKIN OUT,
NICE RISE.
(whistles)
RED ONION MARMALADE--
GIVE IT A THIN COAT.
GET THAT MEAT ON THERE.
SO I GOT
SOME SAUSAGE HERE.
THAT'S READY TO GO BACK
IN THE OVEN COUPLE MINUTES.
OKAY.
PIZZA'S ABOUT READY,
NICE CRUST, BOOM.
JUST DRAPE IT
WITH SOME OF OUR SLAW.
LOOK AT THAT!
CUT IT HERE,
NICE CRISP CRUST.
NO CHEESE AND NO SAUCE.
DUDE, SMOKIN' THE SLAW.
GENIUS. (chuckles)
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
ON THE TOMATO FRONT,
LOOKIN' FOR THE ACID.
YOU'RE GETTING THE ACID
FROM THE ONION, MMM.
BUT THE KICKER--THE SLAW,
BECAUSE OF THE MAYO,
BECAUSE OF THAT FAT,
IS REMINISCENT OF THE FAT
THAT YOU'D NEED
FROM THE CHEESE.
I DON'T KNOW THAT IF YOU
BLIND-FOLDED SOMEBODY,
THE AVERAGE PERSON
WOULD REALLY BE ABLE TO SAY
THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO CHEESE,
AND THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO SAUCE.
I'M NOT GONNA BE ABLE
TO STOP EATING THAT.
HERE'S YOUR SAUSAGE
AND SLAW PIZZA.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
IT'S SO FRESH.
I GOT TO TALK
ABOUT THAT PIZZETTA, MAN.
GIVE THE BOOZE AWAY, AND JUST
CHARGE $9,000 FOR THE PIZZETTA.
I THINK
WHAT REALLY TIES IT TOGETHER
IS ACTUALLY JUST THE SLAW
AND THE ONION.
DUCK CONFIT READY TO GO.
I CAN'T REITERATE THE CARE
THAT GOES INTO THE FRESH
INGREDIENTS INTO THE COOKING.
MOZZARELLA AND GAZPACHO
READY TO GO.
IT'S LIKE SOMETHING THAT YOU
JUST GREW IN YOUR GARDEN.
THIS IS A BLT PIZZA. LOOK AT
THE TOMATOES. THEY'RE HEIRLOOMS.
CRAZY.
FAVORITE THING ON THE MENU...
(man)
COUPLE TACOS FOR YOU.
THE TACOS.
FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
BAHN MI.
SAME THING,
EAT IT EVERY DAY.
BILLY'S VERSION
OF THE VIETNAMESE CLASSIC.
ORDER UP.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SO WHAT DO YOU GOT?
START WITH A PORK LOIN.
FOR THE BAHN MI, LIGHTLY TRIM
IT UP. CUT IT INTO THIRDS.
OKAY.
WE BRINE IT OVERNIGHT,
PUT IN SOME EXTRA FLAVOR,
PULL IT OUT,
AND MARINATE IT.
OKAY.
HOISIN, SRIRACHA,
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
HOW LONG
DOES IT MARINATE?
AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
OUR JALAPEÑO AIOLI.
GOT IT.
WE GOT TO EXTRACT SOME OF
THE LIQUID OUT OF THIS JALAPEÑO.
JUST THE LIQUID ITSELF?
JUST THE LIQUID.
ROUGH-CHOP 'EM.
CRACK OPEN THE CELLS.
YES. PUSH IT THROUGH A CHINOIS.
THIS IS A FINE STRAINER.
PURE JALAPEÑO JUICE.
LOOK AT THAT, MAN.
NOW WE'RE READY FOR OUR AIOLI.
START WITH OUR EGG YOLKS,
FRESH-SQUEEZED LIME JUICE,
MACERATED GARLIC.
BREAKS DOWN REAL EASY.
GIVE IT A LITTLE WHISK.
WHERE'S YOUR OIL?
WILL YOU DO THAT FOR ME?
NOW ANY REASON THAT WE'RE
NOT USING A FOOD PROCESSOR?
I LIKE FOREARM WORKOUTS.
NOW WE ADD OUR JALAPEÑO LIQUID.
SO WE SEASON IT WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF SALT, READY TO GO.
TASTE THIS.
(chuckles)
WITH THAT FRESH
LIME JUICE?
OH, YEAH.
FORGET ABOUT IT.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO SEAR
OUR PORK. FIRST, SOME OIL.
OKAY.
TAKE OUR LOIN,
AND DON'T OVERCROWD OUR PAN.
YOU CROWD THE PAN.
THEY SIT THERE AND STEAM.
THEY DON'T REALLY BUILD A CRUST
TO THE OUTSIDE OF 'EM.
SO YOU'LL MARK THESE OFF
AND THEN FINISH 'EM IN THE OVEN?
YEAH, ABOUT 25 MINUTES
OR SO.
COOL IT DOWN.
TIME TO GO.
YEP. THEY'LL GET A NICE,
THIN SLICE.
OKAY, LOOKIN' GREAT.
A LITTLE ROLL HERE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SLICE.
SOME OF THE KILLER
JALAPEÑO AIOLI.
LAY OUR PORK ON THERE.
OH.
SOME CUCUMBERS, BLANCHED
LONG BEANS, PICKLED CARROTS,
BASIL, BUNCH OF CILANTRO.
OUT OF CONTROL.
NOW THERE'S BAHN MI SANDWICHES
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS PUSHING THE LIMITS.
MMM-MM-MMM.
ARE WE IN FLAVOR TOWN?
YOUR G.P.S. IS WORKING.
THE CRUNCH, FRESH VEGGIES,
NICE ACID.
THE BLANCHED BEANS,
FANTASTIC.
THE PORK IS RIGHT ON POINT.
MMM, PRETTY ROCK STAR.
NICE JOB, BILLY.
THANK YOU.
REALLY NICE JOB.
(man)
AND HERE'S YOUR BAHN MI.
IT HAS A WHOLE BUNCH
OF DIFFERENT FLAVORS IN IT.
THE PORK IS VERY FLAVORFUL.
BAHN MI, JUICY LUCY.
THIS IS THE KIND OF PLACE
WE ALL WANT TO OWN,
KIND OF PLACE WE ALL WANT
TO HANG OUT. CONGRATULATIONS.
UP NEXT...
CHICKEN TAMALE PLATTER'S
COMING OUT.
WE'RE HEADING TO D.C.
EVERYTHING HERE IS REALLY GOOD.
FOR TRUE...
PORK AND CHEESE PUPUSA
PLATTER READY.
SALVADORAN CLASSICS.
MMM.
(grunts) OUT OF BOUNDS.
I'M HERE AT CAPITOL HILL
IN WASHINGTON, D.C,
AT THE WELL-KNOWN
EASTERN MARKET.
NOW ON THE WEEKENDS,
THESE STREETS ARE JUST PACKED
WITH VENDORS SELLING EVERYTHING
FROM PRODUCE TO PANTY HOSE.
SO IF YOU'RE NOT DOWN HERE
GETTING A LITTLE OF THIS,
THAT, AND THE OTHER THING,
YOU'RE PROBABLY HERE
TO CHECK OUT THE LOCAL FAVORITE,
SERVING UP REAL-DEAL MEXICAN
AND SALVADORAN DISHES.
THIS IS TORTILLA CAFE.
SPINACH EMPANADA
PLATTER'S READY.
ONE OF WASHINGTON'S
BEST-KEPT SECRETS.
THIS IS YOUR GO-TO SPOT.
MY GO-TO SPOT.
ORDER OF YUCCA
Y CHICHARRONES READY.
I LOVE
THE CHICKEN FAJITAS.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS REALLY GOOD.
KIM, GOOD AFTERNOON.
HI.
I LOVE COMING HERE,
'CAUSE CATALINA IS AWESOME.
THAT'D BE CATALINA CANALES...
I'VE GOT BEEF
SALVADORIAN SOUP.
WHO'S DOING
THE FAMILY FAVORITES...
I LOVE IT.
SHE GREW UP WITH.
TORTILLAS READY.
WHAT IS THE NUMBER ONE ITEM,
YOU THINK, ON YOUR MENU?
OH, PUPUSAS, HANDS DOWN.
THICK, STUFFED
SALVADORAN TORTILLAS.
AND HOW MANY KIND
DO YOU MAKE?
ABOUT FIVE DIFFERENT KINDS.
BUT THE BIG HIT HERE...
PORK AND CHEESE PUPUSA
PLATTER READY.
I'VE NEVER HAD BETTER.
TRY THEM OTHER PLACES,
BUT THEY'RE NEVER
AS GOOD AS HERE.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE FIRST?
PORK AND CHEESE.
LET'S GO AHEAD AND START OFF
BY CUTTING THE PORK. ADD IT
THE BOWL, LITTLE BIT OF ADOBO.
KIND OF
THE UNIVERSAL SEASONING.
TOTALLY.
WAS THAT A "TOTALLY"
YOU GAVE ME?
YEAH.
(Valley accent)
TOTALLY.
SALT, GARLIC, CUMIN,
FAJITA SEASONING.
(normal voice) THE FAJITA
SEASONING--CAYENNE,
LITTLE PAPRIKA, GRANULATED
GARLIC, GRANULATED ONION.
START MIXING IT IN HERE.
NOW...
GO TO THE STOVETOP.
LET IT COOK.
AND THAT'LL GO
FOR 30 MINUTES.
YEP. THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME FRESH TOMATOES,
RED AND GREEN PEPPERS
AND ONIONS.
RIGHT IN ON TOP.
YEP.
AND THIS CONTINUES
TO COOK.
FOR ANOTHER 30 MINUTES.
YOU SHOULD SMELL THAT.
WE'RE READY TO BLEND IT.
HOW MUCH WE'RE GONNA BLEND IT,
A LITTLE BIT? OR...
WE'RE GONNA BLEND IT
A LOT.
JUST A LOT?
TOTALLY A LOT?
TOTALLY A LOT.
TAKE IT OFF THE STOVETOP.
SCOOP ALL THAT IN THERE.
GO AHEAD AND FIRE IT UP.
AND ARE WE REALLY GOING
TO ALMOST PURéE THIS?
YES. WHEN YOU CUT INTO IT, YOU
SEE THE TEXTURE OF THE PORK,
BUT IT'S VERY FINE
AND MIXED IN WITH THE CHEESE.
THERE WE GO. I'LL GO AHEAD
AND PUT IT ON THIS TRAY HERE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
RICOTTA CHEESE TO IT.
MMM, RICOTTA?
YEP, MOZZARELLA.
SO WE'RE GONNA INCORPORATE
THE CHEESE RIGHT INTO IT.
WE ARE READY TO GO.
NOW WE GET THE MASA.
MASECA.
MASECA--
AND THE DIFFERENCE IS?
MASECA'S JUST PLAIN,
HAS NOTHING IN IT.
MASA IS WHAT WE USE
FOR THE TAMALES.
SO THIS IS JUST STRAIGHT
BLENDED CORN FLOUR?
YEP. THAT'S IT.
ADD SOME WATER TO IT.
THINK I NEED MORE WATER?
I'M GONNA SAY
JUST A TOUCH.
YEAH.
FEELING GOOD?
YEAH, IT'S FEELING
REAL GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE LITTLE BOWL.
YEAH, THE PUPUSA, JUST KIND OF
CREATING A LITTLE HOLE HERE,
THE PORK, THE CHEESE,
AND THE MOZZARELLA
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
WHOA, PUPUSA'S GONE WILD.
FORMING IT.
THEY DROP THE TOP?
YEAH.
WOW, ALL THAT FOR ONE.
ALL THAT FOR ONE.
I KNOW YOU GUYS
WANT TO SEE ME DO THIS.
DOCTOR, DOCTOR. I AM INTIMIDATED
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
DO YOU SEE HOW MUCH THAT IS?
I HAVE A BETTER CHANCE
BURYING MYSELF IN THE SAND
THAN I HAVE COVERING THAT UP.
HERE WE GO.
THE PUPUSA IS LOOS-A.
VERY NICE.
NOT BAD?
NOT BAD AT ALL.
GOOD. NOW ONTO
THE FLATTOP?
YEP, ABOUT TWO MINUTES.
LET'S FLIP IT OVER.
SEE, I LIKE YOURS BETTER.
I THINK MINE GOT OVERZEALOUS.
WE KNOW WHO THE ROOKIE
PUPUSA MAKER IS.
TOTALLY.
HERE, HIDE
MINE UNDERNEATH.
OH. (laughs)
WE'RE READY TO EAT.
(whistles)
MMM.
GOSH, THIS IS GOOD.
PORK AND PORK
WITH A LITTLE CHEESE PUPUSA.
FLAVOR'S GREAT.
I LOVE THE CRISPINESS
AND THE TRUE SALVADORAN
CONDIMENTS, MMM.
THE PICKLED CABBAGE--
YOU MAKE THAT YOURSELF?
YES.
GOT A NICE SWEETNESS
TO IT.
DO YOU GUYS MAKE
YOUR OWN SALSAS HERE AS WELL?
WE DO.
LOOK AT THAT BITE.
MMM. YOU GOT TO COME TRY THIS.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
OUT OF BOUNDS.
TWO MORE MINUTES
ON THOSE PUPUSAS.
DELICIOUS. IT'S JUST
A REALLY GREAT DISH.
MOIST ON THE INSIDE
AND VERY FLAVORFUL.
CARNE ASADA COMING OUT.
YOU WALK BY. YOU CAN SMELL
THE DELICIOUS FOOD
COMING OUT
OF THIS RESTAURANT.
THERE IS NO BETTER FOOD
ON CAPITOL HILL.
AND IT'S TOTALLY AUTHENTIC.
TOTALLY.
THIS IS OUR TRADITIONAL
BEEF SALVADORIAN SOUP.
IF YOU GO TO EL SALVADOR,
YOU'RE DEFINITELY--
THIS IS HOW
THEY MAKE IT. MMM.
IT'S A TASTE OF TRADITION
RIGHT THERE.
MMM.
AND SO IS THIS.
CHICKEN TAMALE COMING OUT.
TAMALES FOR CHRISTMAS.
THERE YOU GO.
THE TAMALES ARE DELICIOUS.
THE CHICKEN TAMALE IS PRETTY
GOOD, ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
NOW WHAT ARE WE INTO?
CHICKEN TAMALE.
WE'RE GONNA GO OFF
AND START WITH CHICKEN BREAST.
CUT 'EM UP INTO PIECES
THAT WE'RE GONNA BE ADDING
TO THE TAMALE.
WE'RE NOT SHREDDING THIS.
NO, NO, NO.
WE'RE NOT SHREDDING IT.
I'M GONNA SEASON THE CHICKEN,
ADD SOME OIL,
FAJITA SEASONING,
GARLIC, ADOBO, AND SALT.
THE ADOBO'S THE KICKER.
SO LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GET IT FIRED UP,
GO OVER TO THE STOVETOP.
HOT PAN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD WATER TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A VEGGIE PURéE--
TOMATOES, GREEN PEPPERS,
RED PEPPERS, CELERY, AND ONION
BLENDED TOGETHER.
COOK IT DOWN ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
LET'S MAKE OUR MASA.
YEAH.
LET'S START ON THAT.
MASECA.
BLENDED CORN FLOUR.
ADD SOME WATER TO IT.
LOOK AT THIS FOREARM,
MORE WATER.
PRACTICALLY A MASECA
SWIMMING POOL.
HOLY CREAMY.
TOTALLY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT
TO THE STOVETOP.
WE'RE GONNA COOK THIS?
GIVE IT SOME FLAVOR.
OKAY, WELL, THAT'LL HELP
TIGHTEN IT UP.
OH, YEAH. ADD OIL, SOME SALT,
A BLEND OF FAJITA, ADOBO,
AND COMINO, THE SAME LIQUID
THAT WE ADDED TO THE CHICKEN.
NOW HOW LONG
WE GONNA COOK THIS?
UNTIL IT SOLIDIFIES,
CONSTANTLY DOING THIS.
YOU HAVE GOT
TO BE KIDDING ME.
IT LOOKS LIKE POLENTA.
YOU GOT THAT?
I GOT IT.
WANT ME TO SPOT YOU?
WE'RE GOOD.
LET ME JUST GET A LITTLE--
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
ARE WE WRAPPING THESE
IN CORN HUSKS?
PLANTAIN. MEXICAN IS CORN.
SALVADORIAN IS PLANTAIN.
SO I'LL TAKE A SPOONFUL.
PUT IT RIGHT IN THE CENTER.
I'LL TAKE A SPOONFUL,
AND GUESS WHAT'LL HAPPEN?
MINE WILL BE
TOO BIG AGAIN.
TAKE A PIECE OF CHICKEN,
PUT IT RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE,
TWO OLIVES AND--
OH, GARBANZO BEANS.
YEAH, AND RAW POTATOES.
ROLL UP OUR TAMALE.
VERY GOOD.
HOW MANY HAVE YOU MADE
AT A TIME?
EASILY ABOUT 25.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK
FOR 25 TAMALES.
OH, YEAH. IT IS.
DO WE STEAM THESE?
YEAH, WE DO.
IN WE GO.
IN WE GO,
POT OF BOILING WATER.
HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA HAVE TO STEAM?
45 MINUTES.
HERS LOOKS WAY BETTER.
WE'LL UNWRAP IT
ON THE TABLE HERE.
GET RID OF THE BANANA LEAF?
YEP.
PICO DE GALLO?
PICO DE GALLO.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY TO DO IT
RIGHT THERE.
SO CREAMY. THE FLAVOR
IN THE MASA IS HUGE.
I LOVE THE GARBANZO BEANS
AND THE OLIVES GOING IN THERE.
THIS IS WITHOUT QUESTION
ONE OF THE TASTIEST TAMALES.
GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
RIDICULOUS.
CHICKEN TAMALE PLATTER'S
COMING OUT.
THESE ARE
ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
IT'S WHAT I'D ORDER
NEXT TIME I'M BACK.
CORN TORTILLAS READY
FOR THE SOUP.
IT'S REALLY NICE TO HAVE
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
TEX-MEX FAJITA.
FANTASTIC.
TAMALES--KILLER,
PUPUSA--ENORMOUS.
ALL I NEED HERE IS A SMALL BED.
IT WAS THAT GOOD.
NEXT STOP...
1 90-MINUTE FOR YOU.
WE'RE HEADING
TO PHILADELPHIA...
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
FOR TOFU?
ANY TIME YOU HAVE A CONCERN
WITH TOFU, MY RECOMMENDATION...
INTO THE DEEP FRYER.
VERY NICE.
I GOT ONE FOR YOU.
I'M IN THE KENSINGTON
NEIGHBORHOOD OF PHILADELPHIA,
ABOUT 2 MILES
OUTSIDE OF OLD CITY,
WHERE A HUSBAND AND WIFE TEAM,
BOTH BORN AND RAISED IN PHILLY,
HAVE TAKEN OVER
AND RENOVATED A 1920s BAR,
AND THEY'RE SERVING UP
AMERICAN REGIONAL BAR FOOD.
THIS IS MEMPHIS TAPROOM.
(man) KIELBASY
AND SAUERKRAUT.
SAUSAGE WITH SAUERKRAUT--
IT'S TOP-NOTCH.
BURGERS ON THE GRILL.
THE FOOD HERE IS GREAT.
I JUST REALLY ENJOY IT.
CHICKEN FRIED CHICKEN.
FANTASTIC.
THE CHICKEN IS AWESOME.
FISH AND CHIPS!
A LOT OF FOOD THAT JUST GOES
REALLY WELL WITH BEER.
1 90-MINUTE FOR YOU.
NO SURPRISE COMING FROM
BEER LOVER BRENDAN HARTRANFT...
I MEAN, IT'S MY PASSION.
WHO OPENED THIS BEER BAR
WITH HIS WIFE LEIGH MAIDA...
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
THEN BROUGHT IN
CHEF JESSE KIMBALL
TO DO THE COOKING.
SWISS CHARD MAC AND CHEESE,
JACKFRUIT CAKES.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF ORIGINAL
STUFF ON THIS MENU.
CAULIFLOWER TAJINE.
THE MAJORITY OF THIS
IS YOUR RECIPE.
EVERYTHING.
CREATIVE, MAN.
(Jesse) WATERMELON SALAD.
WATERMELON SALAD WITH
PORK RILLONS BABY ARUGULA,
AND PICKLED RED ONION.
A SALTY, SWEET MASTERPIECE.
WE GOT PORK BELLY.
WHICH YOU MAKE BACON
OUT OF.
YEP. CUT THIS
INTO CUBES.
AND WE'RE GONNA SLOW-COOK IT
IN SOME LARD.
SO EVERY BIT OF IT JUST GONNA
BE UNCTUOUS AND DELICIOUS.
GET NICE SQUARES,
PRETTY BIG.
NOW WE NEED SOME SPICES.
CLOVE. GRIND THESE UP.
FRESH SPICES, WHOLE SPICES,
BETTER FOOD.
GOT SOME CLOVES, WHITE PEPPER,
FRESH GROUND, GINGER.
BIG FAN OF MARY ANN.
I LIKE MARY ANN BETTER.
LITTLE NUTMEG.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY TO DO IT.
CINNAMON.
CINNAMON-AMON-AMON.
NOW WE'LL MIX PORK BELLY,
KOSHER SALT.
COAT THAT PORK.
SO LET THIS GO
FOR 24 HOURS.
PUT IT IN
THE WALK-IN OVERNIGHT,
AND IT SHOULD HAVE
A NICE STICKINESS TO IT.
IT HAS ABSORBED
THE GREATNESS.
THERE WE GO,
INTO THE POT.
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE SEAR ON IT.
YEP.
HEAT IT UP A BIT
AND THEN DROP THE LARD IN.
COVER IT COMPLETELY.
CONTINUES TO BUILD FLAVOR.
YEAH. NOW WE'LL COVER IT
AND PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
FOR 4 OR 5 HOURS?
YEAH, 225, 250.
AND IT'LL JUST BE
NICE AND TENDER.
THEY SHOULD BE
JUST ABOUT DONE.
(whistles)
TAKE A LOOKY LOO
AT THAT.
OH, DUDE.
SEE? OH, THAT'S GREAT.
CAMERA ATE IT.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA COOL IT DOWN
IN ITS FAT AND THEN FRY IT UP.
GORGEOUS.
BUILD A SALAD.
WE GOT
SUGARCANE VINAIGRETTE.
SUGARCANE VINEGAR.
SUGARCANE VINEGAR, YEAH.
WOW.
WATERMELON, ARUGULA, AND FINISH
IT WITH PICKLED RED ONIONS.
PUT IT ON A PLATE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE,
PORK, THE WATERMELON,
THE ONIONS, AND THE ARUGULA.
IT GOES TOGETHER SO WELL,
THE SALT, THE SWEET, THE ONION.
BOW-BOW-BOW. IT'S JUST BOUNCING
AROUND IN MY MOUTH.
I WOULD CALL THIS
THE YOGI BEAR,
'CAUSE I FEEL LIKE I JUST ATE
A PICNIC BASKET.
I MEAN, I GOT IT ALL, MAN.
HEY, BOO BOO.
(imitating Yogi Bear) I'M
SMARTER THAN THE AVERAGE SALAD.
THIS IS THE PORK RILLONS.
OH, THAT SALAD.
IT'S SO GOOD.
WITH THE FRESH WATERMELON,
IT'S JUST REALLY WONDERFUL.
(Jesse)
BLUE BURGER WITH BACON.
EVERYTHING IS DELICIOUS.
(Jesse) FIRING PIEROGIES.
JESSE PUTS A LOT
OF TIME AND ENERGY
INTO MAKING A GOOD MEAL.
OYSTER PO'BOY.
ESPECIALLY WITH HIS
FAVORITE INGREDIENT.
WE USE AS MUCH BEER
IN OUR FOOD AS WE CAN.
LIKE HUMMUS WITH HEFEWEIZEN.
HEFEWEIZEN HUMMUS.
A BAVARIAN-STYLE WHEAT BEER.
REAL SPICY, DELICIOUS.
PILSNER-BRINED HOT WINGS.
HOT WINGS.
EVEN BEER-BATTERED
FRIED DILL PICKLES.
THE FRIED PICKLES ARE AWESOME.
WITH A DIPPING SAUCE
THAT STARTS AT THE SOURCE.
THIS IS HORSERADISH,
DOESN'T COME IN A JAR.
IT GROWS IN THE GROUND.
THAT'S A ROOT.
JUST PEEL THAT, CHOP IT UP.
ARE WE GONNA BREAK IT DOWN
ANY FINER THAN THIS?
IN THE BLENDER WE ARE.
DIG THAT.
SALT AND PEPPER
AND BUTTERMILK.
WE CALL THIS A HORSERADISH
BUTTERMILK SAUCE,
'CAUSE WE PUT IN HORSERADISH
AND BUTTERMILK.
WHO WOULD HAVE KNOWN?
WE'VE GOT MAYONNAISE.
BUZZ THAT RIGHT IN.
JUST GETS IT REAL SMOOTH.
BUT THE POTENCY--
THAT'S HOW MY HAIR
GOT LIKE THIS.
MAKE SOME BEER BATTER--
FLOUR, SUGAR...
BAKING SODA
AND BAKING POWDER.
WHISK IT UP, BUTTERMILK FIRST.
JUST A BIT OF THAT.
AND THEN POUR THAT BEER
RIGHT IN THERE.
OH.
ICE-COLD BEER.
NOW IS THIS LIKE
A PANCAKE BATTER
WHERE YOU DON'T WANT
TO OVERMIX IT?
YEAH, YOU DON'T WANT IT
TO BE TOUGH.
YOU WANT TO BE NICE
TO THE PICKLE.
LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
LET'S FRY SOME PICKLES.
GIVE IT A LITTLE WIGGLE.
LITTLE PICKLE WIGGLE.
WHAT KIND OF OIL
ARE WE IN?
100% PEANUT OIL,
GOOD FLAVOR, NICE AND CRISPY.
HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA GO?
THREE, FOUR MINUTES
TILL THEY'RE GOLDEN BROWN.
LOOK AT THOSE.
OH, YEAH. IN THE BOWL,
HORSERADISH BUTTERMILK,
KOSHER DILLS.
THOSE ARE BIG AND HOT.
THEY'RE BIG AND HOT.
WOW. THE HORSERADISH
BUTTERMILK
IS PURE, SIMPLE,
AND MEGA-FLAVOR.
THE BATTER IS OUTRAGEOUS.
BIG PORTION, MMM.
GOOD PICKLE. THE FRESH
HORSERADISH AND THE BUTTERMILK--
THAT REIGNS SUPREME.
GOOD INGREDIENTS.
OH, DYNAMITE.
FRIED DILL PICKLES.
I DON'T KNOW
ANY OTHER PLACE
THAT DOES IT AS WELL
AS THESE GUYS.
AND THE DIPPING SAUCE,
NICE TANGY FLAVOR TO IT.
BEER-BATTERED KOSHER DILLS.
(exhales deeply)
I KNOW.
SMOKING.
IT'S EXCITING.
AND ON THIS BAR FOOD MENU...
THEY'VE GOT SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY.
THEY'VE GOT THINGS THAT ARE
FRIED. THEY'VE GOT BURGERS.
THEY'VE EVEN GOT...
TOFU?
TOFU.
YEP, VEGETARIAN COOKING.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
WHEN WE GET BACK.
AT THE MEMPHIS TAPROOM
IN PHILADELPHIA...
WHO'S GETTING THIS LAGER?
CHEF JESSE KIMBALL'S CRANKING
OUT BAR FOOD WITH ATTITUDE.
PORK RILLONS WATERMELON SALAD.
AND OH, YEAH,
A WHOLE VEGAN MENU, TOO.
(Jesse)
ROASTED CAULIFLOWER TAJINE.
TAKES VEGAN COOKING
TO THE NEXT LEVEL.
SMOKED COCONUT CLUB.
THE SMOKED COCONUT CLUB
IS ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER HAD
SMOKED COCONUT BEFORE.
HOW ABOUT WITH TOFU AND MAYO
MADE FROM TOMATOES?
WE ARE IN AN OLD-SCHOOL
NEIGHBORHOOD OF PHILADELPHIA.
YEAH.
THE BUILDING
IS FROM THE 1920s.
SURVIVED PROHIBITION.
TOFU?
TOFU.
LET'S SEE IT.
GONNA CUT EIGHT PIECES.
ARE WE GONNA THROW PRESS THIS
OR ANYTHING?
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
HO! ANY TIME YOU HAVE A CONCERN
WITH TOFU, MY RECOMMENDATION...
INTO THE DEEP FRYER.
VERY NICE.
GOING DOWN. SEE,
THE GREAT THING ABOUT THIS--
YOU'RE GETTING SOME OF THE WATER
OUT. TOFU GETS KIND OF SPONGY.
YOU CAN EITHER PRESS THE TOFU,
GETS NICE AND FIRM,
OR YOU CAN DO THIS METHOD, WHICH
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG WITH.
YO! WE GOT TOFU.
GONNA MARINATE THIS IN GARLIC,
LEMON JUICE, PARSLEY, OIL.
AND THIS
WILL MARINATE OVERNIGHT?
YEAH. THEN WE HAVE
A SMOKED COCONUT.
WE'RE LITERALLY GONNA SMOKE
THIS STUFF?
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN A SMOKER.
OH. THAT'S WHAT I MEANT.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
FIND THE SWEET SPOT
AND THERE IT IS.
THERE WE GO!
IF YOU PUT IT IN A 400-DEGREE
OVEN FOR A FEW MINUTES,
IT WILL PULL THE MEAT AWAY
FROM THE SHELL,
MAKE IT EASIER TO GET OUT.
GET IN THERE WITH A KNIFE,
AND IT SHOULD POP RIGHT OUT.
REALLY.
LET'S GO THIS WAY.
I LOVE THIS GUY.
WE JUST GIVE 'EM
SOME THIN SLICES.
RIGHT INTO THE BOWL.
DUDE.
GET ENOUGH COCONUT TO
MAKE A FEW SANDWICHES.
KOSHER SALT.
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
ONLY FRESH GROUND.
HE GROUND THIS HIMSELF.
IT'S GOT A NICE DUST TO IT.
DARK BROWN SUGAR.
AND THAT'S IT,
JUST A LITTLE CURE ON THIS.
ABSORB SOME OF THAT FLAVOR.
IT'LL LOSE SOME OF ITS MOISTURE.
WE LET THIS HANG OUT
FOR 24 HOURS.
THEN WE'LL GO
TO THE SMOKER?
YEAH, FOR FIVE HOURS.
READY TO GO.
WHAT'S NEXT?
LET'S MAKE A SANDWICH.
GOT SOME TOFU ON THE GRILL.
GET A NICE SLICE OF TOMATO.
GIVE THESE A FLIP.
ALL RIGHT, WE'VE GOT OUR TOAST,
CLUB WHEAT.
WE'VE GOT THIS VEGAN
TOMATO MAYONNAISE WE MADE
WITH LEMON JUICE,
TOMATO PASTE, DIJON MUSTARD,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
AND THEN SOME OIL.
NICE.
PUT THE TOFU ON THE BREAD,
ADD SOME BIBB LETTUCE,
NICE FRESH TOMATO, AND THEN SOME
OF THIS COCONUT OFF OUR SMOKER.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND UP ON HERE, THIS IS
THE VEGAN CLUB SANDWICH.
THERE ARE PEOPLE BOOKING
FLIGHTS RIGHT NOW, JESS.
(laughs)
OKAY.
THE MAYO IS OUTRAGEOUS. BIG TANG
COMING OUT OF THAT TOMATO MAYO.
THE COCONUT WORKS PERFECTLY.
I KNOW, MOM.
I'M EATING TOFU.
CHEF, YOU'RE OUTSTANDING.
SMOKED COCONUT CLUB.
THAT LOOKS LIKE BACON,
BUT THAT'S NOT BACON.
IT'S SMOKED COCONUT.
I'M NOT A VEGETARIAN, BUT...
IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT'S CRAZY.
COCONUT CLUB!
LOTS OF FLAVOR.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BEER-BATTER KOSHER DILLS.
VERY CREATIVE, INVENTIVE.
THIS IS THE PORK RILLONS SALAD.
THIS IS ALL FRESH AND DELICIOUS.
CHEF, YOU UNDERSTAND IT. YOU
EMBRACE ALL THE INGREDIENTS.
IT'S AN ORCHESTRA, MAN.
YOU GOT TO COME MEET CHEF JESS.
THIS DUDE'S OFF THE HOOK.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LOOK AT ME.
DON'T TOUCH IT.
(mumbles)
DON'T EVEN TOUCH.