HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
♪ AH ♪
SOUP...
MMM. SUPER SAVORY.
AND SANDWICHES.
(woman) HOT BLONDE.
THE SANDWICH IS REALLY
CALLED HOT BLONDE.
YEAH. YEAH.
AND JUST I HAPPEN
TO BE HERE.
IN SACRAMENTO, CALIFORNIA...
MAC 'N' CHEESE.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
YOU KNOW IT'S GONNA
BE DELICIOUS.
TAKING BACON CHEESEBURGERS...
(whistling)
TO THE MAX.
GRAND SLAM. AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
IN INDIANAPOLIS...
ONE ORDER UP.
THE 47-YEAR-OLD LANDMARK...
IT'S ONE OF A KIND.
SERVIN' UP LOCAL FLAVOR...
MEAT LOAF,
TABLE FIVE UP.
AND, OH, YEAH,
A LITTLE ITALIAN, TOO.
THAT'S A REAL GOOD
MEATBALL SANDWICH.
AND OUTSIDE PHILADELPHIA...
CREAMED PEAS
AND PROSCIUTTO UP.
THE 145-YEAR-OLD TAVERN...
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
LIKE HOME.
DOIN' A ROCKIN' RAVIOLI...
MMM.
AND A SOUP...
I LOVE IT.
SERIOUSLY?
THAT'S SNAPPIN'.
GET THAT TURTLE MEAT
NICE AND TENDER.
MMM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN LAND PARK.
IT'S A COOL, LITTLE NEIGHBORHOOD
IN SACRAMENTO.
AND WE'RE ABOUT A MILE EAST
OF JAMIE'S, YOU KNOW,
WITH THE REALLY KILLER
STEAK SANDWICHES?
AND WE'RE HERE
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT I HEAR HAS GOT
A REALLY OFF-THE-HOOK SPIN
ON BACON CHEESEBURGERS.
THIS IS DAD'S KITCHEN.
DAD'S BURGER. ENJOY.
YOU HAVE TO GET
THE DAD'S BURGER.
UNLIKE ANY OTHER BURGER
I'VE EVER HAD.
THE BEST PART ABOUT IT IS
THE BACON AND THE BLUE CHEESE
LITERALLY SEARED
RIGHT INTO THE BURGER.
THREE DAD'S BURGERS,
MEDIUM-RARE.
AN AMAZING
COMBINATION.
THAT'S MADE IT
THE TOP SELLER.
YOU ALWAYS WANT TO COME BACK
AND HAVE IT AGAIN.
SO WHEN JULIO PEIX
AND CHRISTINE COLLINS
BOUGHT THE JOINT
NEARLY TWO YEARS AGO...
ALL RIGHT, I GOT
TWO DAD'S BURGERS.
THEY MADE SURE
TO KEEP IT ON THE MENU,
SO KITCHEN MANAGER
LUIS BECERA...
THANK YOU.
COULD KEEP ON CRANKIN' OUT
MORE THAN 7,000 A YEAR.
SO JUICY--
BEST BURGER IN TOWN.
LET'S DO
THE DAD'S BURGER.
OKAY.
CHOP THE BACON--
SMALL SQUARES.
THE BACON
IS GOING ON TOP.
YES, KINDA CRUST IT
ON THE BURGER.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA
CRUST IT.
YEP.
MAKE A LITTLE BED OF BACON.
IT'S GOING WITH BLUE CHEESE.
INTERESTING.
PEOPLE LOVE BACON
AND BLUE CHEESE.
8 OUNCES.
SO YOU'RE HOPING THAT
THAT ALL STICKS TOGETHER.
YES.
YOU THINK
YOU GOT IT?
YEAH. DON'T SAY
ANYTHING.
WHAT, IS IT QUIET TIME
RIGHT NOW?
YEAH, SHH.
WE DON'T WANT
TO SCARE IT?
CONCENTRATION--THERE WE GO.
THAT'S A BURGER RIGHT THERE.
WHO MADE THIS UP?
I DID.
THIS WAS YOUR IDEA?
YES.
THAT'S AWESOME.
NOW WHAT?
THE ALEPPO SPREAD.
THE ALEPPO?
ALEPPO CHILI SPREAD, YEAH.
ALEPPO IS A CHILI FROM SYRIA.
IT TASTES
LIKE HOT PAPRIKA.
YEAH.
WE HAVE ROASTED GARLIC.
WE NEED TO DRAIN IT OFF.
AND WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THE OIL?
WE'RE GONNA USE IT
FOR THE SPREAD, ACTUALLY.
OH, IT SMELLS
AWESOME.
A COUPLE EGGS.
THAT'LL WORK
AS SOME BINDER.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
PEPPER--BLEND IT UP.
WE'RE NOW PUTTING IN
THE GARLIC OIL.
ALEPPO PEPPER
AND LEMON JUICE.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
I'M GOING TO CRUSH YOU.
OH, YEAH.
YEAH.
SQUISHY.
AND THAT'S IT--
ALEPPO SPREAD RIGHT THERE.
(normal voice)
GET ME ALL THAT TO GO.
TAKE IT.
(Guy) LET'S MAKE
THE BURGER.
(Luis) ALL RIGHT.
OIL'S DOWN.
BACON GOES DOWN FIRST.
YEP, SALT
AND PEPPER.
WE NEED TO USE
THIS PRESS.
WE'VE GOTTA MAKE SURE THE BACON
COOKS ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
YEAH.
'CAUSE IF IT DOESN'T COOK
ALL THE WAY THROUGH,
YOU'RE GONNA...
AND WHEN YOU FLIP IT,
ALL THE FLAVORS COME OUT.
GO.
FLIP THE BURGER.
THERE IT IS.
HOLY CRUST-IFICATION.
AND IT'S JUST SITTIN' THERE,
COOKIN' IN THAT
BACON FAT GALORE.
HAMBURGER BUN.
HE'S SO KILLER.
HERE WE GO.
THE BACON SMASHED ON IT...
(whistles)
AND YOU GUYS MAKE
YOUR OWN FRIES, TOO?
YES, EVERY MORNING.
LET'S PUT SOME SPREAD.
GOOD FRY, MAN.
THANK YOU.
STAND BACK.
THIS COULD GET MESSY.
DRUMROLL, PLEASE.
(clicks tongue)
(laughs)
(moans)
LOOK AT THE JUICE.
DUDE. IT'S PROBABLY THE JUICIEST
BURGER YOU'RE GONNA TRY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS
THE BOUNDS...
(squeaking)
AND THIS...
(bell dings)
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THIS THING
IS RIGHTEOUS!
THANK YOU.
DUDE.
TAKE A LOOK HERE
AT HOW THE BACON
AND THE CHEESE HAVE JUST
MELDED--KILLER BURGER.
THIS IS A CROSS BETWEEN
HODAD'S AND SQUEEZE IN.
I MEAN, THIS IS--THIS IS
UP THERE AT THAT LEVEL OF--
OF BURGER GREATNESS--
SOMETHING SO SIMPLE
DONE SO RIGHT.
GRAND SLAM.
AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
(man) DAD'S REUBEN.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
EVERY TIME I COME HERE,
I WILL HAVE IT.
THE FOOD'S JUST KILLER. IT'S
JUST GOOD NEIGHBORHOOD FOOD.
MAC 'N' CHEESE--
HERE YOU GO.
THERE'S A BEAUTIFUL PATIO,
SO WE EAT OUT THERE A LOT.
IT'S A HANGOUT.
THANKS.
WE'RE A FUN JOINT,
BASICALLY, WITH GOOD FOOD.
(Christine) ONION RINGS.
THEIR FOOD
IS TRULY AMAZING.
THEY'RE PASSIONATE ABOUT IT,
SO IT SHOWS ON THE PLATE.
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH
READY.
EVERYTHING'S MADE
FROM SCRATCH DAILY.
FROM FRESH-BAKED
MEAT LOAF...
WONDERFUL,
MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
TO HAND-TOSSED ONION RINGS
WITH A BALSAMIC REDUCTION.
THESE ARE DELICIOUS, AND I'M
AN ONION RING FREAK. MMM.
THEY'RE EVEN FRESH-ROASTIN'
THE CHICKEN
FOR THIS SANDWICH.
HEY, GUYS,
HOT BLONDE.
IT'S AWESOME. I LOVE AVOCADO,
AND I LOVE CHICKEN.
(Luis)
HOT BLONDE SANDWICH.
FOR THE WHO?
HOT BLONDE. NOT YOU.
WAIT A SECOND...
THAT'S THE NAME
OF THE SANDWICH.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S NOT ABOUT ME.
YEAH. NO.
NO. THE SANDWICH IS REALLY
CALLED HOT BLONDE.
NO. YEAH. YEAH.
AND JUST I HAPPEN
TO BE HERE.
SPLIT HER IN HALF,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER--
LET'S GO TO THE OVEN.
25 MINUTES AT 325?
YEAH.
ROASTED CHICKEN--
LET IT COOL.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE MEAT OFF IT.
YES.
NOW WHAT?
PREPARE THE PEPPER
PLANT SAUCE--KETCHUP.
SO WE'RE PREPARING
THE PEPPER PLANT SAUCE.
YES. ROASTED GARLIC
AND ROASTED CHILI FLAKES,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
PEPPER.
GOT ONION POWDER
AND PEPERONCINI JUICE.
THE MARINADE
OF THE PEPERONCINI'S THERE.
YES.
INTERESTING.
THERE WE GO.
NOTHIN' WRONG WITH THAT.
WHAT'S THAT GOIN' ON AGAIN?
ON THE HOT BLONDE SANDWICH.
THANK YOU.
GARLIC SPREAD.
IT'S THE SAME AS THE ALEPPO
SPREAD, BUT WITHOUT ALEPPO.
WITHOUT THE ALEPPO.
BROWN MUSTARD. THIS IS
OUR PEPPER PLANT SAUCE.
THAT WE PREPARED?
YEAH. SWISS CHEESE,
FRESH TOMATOES,
AVOCADO, CUCUMBERS,
ROASTED RED ONIONS.
IS THIS JUST
A GAME NOW
TO SEE HOW MUCH YOU CAN
PUT ON THE SANDWICH?
NO.
SPINACH.
WE STILL HAVE THE CHICKEN
TO PUT ON IT.
OH, YEAH.
AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT THAT IN THE, UH...
PANINI PRESS.
OIL ON THE PANINI.
AND HOW LONG?
FOUR MINUTES.
READY TO ROLL?
IS IT DONE?
YES, IT'S READY.
PULL IT.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE WE GO.
OH, HO, THIS IS
GONNA BE GOOD.
(mumbling) IT'S GOOD.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THANKS.
(normal voice) IT'S LIKE
A CLUB SANDWICH GONE WILD. MMM.
THIS IS THE KIND OF SANDWICH
MY MOM WOULD FLIP OUT FOR.
I STILL DON'T KNOW WHY
IT'S HOT BLONDE.
I JUST WISH YOU WOULD
COME OUT WITH IT AND SAY
THAT YOU DID NAME IT
AFTER ME. I UNDERSTAND.
HOW BLONDE, TABLE FOUR,
THANK YOU!
(bell dings)
IT'S AWESOME. IT'S SO GOOD.
THE CREAMINESS OF THE AVOCADO
MIXED WITH
PEPPER PLANT SAUCE,
WHICH JUST GIVES IT
A LITTLE KICK,
ALL IN BETWEEN THE CRUNCHY
BREAD--IT'S PERFECT.
HUH. DON'T AIR THAT.
SHE'S BETTER
THAN ME AT IT.
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH,
TABLE ONE.
YOU KNOW IT'S GONNA
BE DELICIOUS.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
WALKING INTO A PLACE
THAT YOU'VE BEEN TO
YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
HI, JULIO.
CONGRATULATIONS,
YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A REALLY FUN PLACE,
AND THE DAD'S BURGER--
OUTTA BOUNDS. YOU GOTTA
COME TRY THIS BURGER.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO INDIANAPOLIS...
THE BEST--
IT REALLY IS.
FOR A LITTLE LOCAL FLAVOR.
WE'RE SERVING UP THE STARCHY
PASTA WITH POTATOES?
WE ARE, YEAH.
MMM.
I'M ABOUT 5 MILES EAST
OF THE CIRCLE,
THE CENTER OF INDIANAPOLIS,
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
OF IRVINGTON,
AND I'VE GOT ONE OF THOSE GREAT
TRIPLE "D" STORIES--
LOCAL HANGOUT,
ABOUT READY TO CLOSE DOWN,
UNTIL A MOTHER AND SON TEAM UP,
BUY THE PLACE,
RESURRECT IT,
AND KEEP A TRADITION ALIVE.
THIS IS INDY'S
HISTORIC STEER-IN.
MEAT LOAF
AND MASHED POTATOES UP.
I LOVE IT.
HERE'S YOUR
FRIED CHICKEN.
BEEN A BIG PART
OF THE COMMUNITY
SINCE I WAS
A LITTLE GIRL.
(man) TURKEY
WITH CORN'S UP.
EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD
NEEDS A JOINT LIKE THIS, HUH?
AMEN TO THAT.
BUT THE NEIGHBORHOOD ALMOST
LOST THIS ONE THREE YEARS AGO.
IF IT WASN'T FOR CASEY,
IT PROBABLY WOULD HAVE BEEN
SHUT DOWN FOREVER.
YOU'RE UP.
THAT'D BE LONG-TIME CUSTOMER
CASEY KEHRER...
DROPPIN' FRIES.
BEEN COMIN' HERE SINCE I WAS
5 OR 6 YEARS OLD.
IN THE WINDOW.
WHO CONVINCED
HIS MOM BARBARA...
ONE ORDER UP.
TO BUY THE JOINT.
WHERE DID YOU GUYS
GET THE MONEY?
WE USED
HER RETIREMENT MONEY.
UH, YEAH, YEAH.
AND, UH...
WENT FOR BROKE.
YES, YOU DID.
TWIN STEER PLATTER.
KEEPING THE OLD FAVORITES...
MMM. IT'S
ONE OF A KIND.
AND ADDING THEIR OWN.
(Casey) LASAGNA'S UP.
IS YOUR FAMILY ITALIAN?
NO, THEY'RE NOT.
WE'RE GERMAN-IRISH.
MY DAD LIVED NEAR A BUNCH
OF ITALIANS, THOUGH.
HE SURE DID.
MEATBALL SUB.
IT'S A GOOD, GENUINE
ITALIAN MEATBALL SANDWICH.
IN TO MAKE
SOME MEATBALLS...
ALL RIGHT,
WE START WITH VEAL...
GROUND CHUCK.
SOME SWEET
ITALIAN SAUSAGE.
THREE MEATS?
AT A BURGER JOINT--DUDE.
EGGS, BREAD CRUMBS--
WE GRIND THESE
FROM FRENCH BAGUETTES
OURSELVES.
I LOVE IT.
FRESH BASIL.
MINCED GARLIC,
OREGANO.
MINCED ONIONS.
PARMESAN CHEESE, PEPPER,
SALT, A LITTLE MILK.
THIS IS
LIKE MEATBALL 101.
IT'S ALL HERE.
FOLD THAT TOGETHER.
GO FOR IT.
LET'S MAKE MEATBALLS.
YOU GONNA
WEIGH 'EM OUT?
NO, WE JUST KINDA
EYEBALL 'EM.
THAT'S A BIG ONE.
THAT'S A RACQUETBALL.
SO YOU PUT 'EM ON THE TRAY,
COOK 'EM OFF AT 350,
LET 'EM BROWN UP?
RIGHT.
SO NOW WE'RE MAKIN'
THE MARINARA FOR THE MEATBALLS.
YES. WE TAKE OUR
ROMA TOMATOES...
BOILED, PEELED,
SEEDED.
POUR THEM
INTO THE POT.
WHOA. I WAS THERE FOR YA
EVERY STEP OF THE WAY.
I COULD SEE THAT.
JUST GONNA LET THOSE TOMATOES
COOK DOWN FOR AN HOUR.
EXACTLY.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SAUTé
ONIONS, ANCHOVIES.
THAT'S A NEW ONE. A WHOLE MESS
OF GARLIC--I LIKE THAT.
LET THAT ALL
COOK DOWN.
THAT GOES STRAIGHT
INTO THE TOMATO SAUCE.
AND WE'LL LET THIS SIMMER
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
WHAT'S THE FINAL STEP?
FRESH HERBS--
OREGANO, PARSLEY.
A MESS OF BASIL.
SALT AND PEPPER--
THEN WE STIR IT UP.
THEN WE ADD A CAN
OF TOMATO SAUCE.
HIT IT WITH
THE IMMERSION BLENDER.
WE GOTTA GET YOU A BIGGER
ONE OF THOSE, BROTHER.
YEAH, I NEED
A BIGGER ONE.
LET IT SIMMER FOR ABOUT A
HALF-HOUR, ADD PARMESAN CHEESE.
THAT'S SOME PARMESAN.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD TO GO.
YEAH. WE WARM
THE MEATBALLS UP.
REHEAT 'EM
ON THE FLATTOP.
RIGHT. WHILE THOSE ARE COOKIN',
TAKE OUR BREAD...
WITH THE MARINARA.
LOTS OF CHEESE.
AND PUT THAT
UNDER THE SALAMANDER.
CHEESE IS MELTED.
NICE.
YEAH, LOOK AT THOSE.
THAT'S A BIG PORTION.
A LITTLE MARINARA--
MARINARA ON TOP THERE.
GUESS WHAT? HOT.
OH, I HAVE TO CUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, THAT'S A REAL GOOD
MEAT LOAF SANDWICH.
WHAT'S YOUR LAST NAME?
KEHRER.
OR KEHR-LIONI?
YEAH ON THE "ONI."
A LITTLE KEHR-LIONI. YEAH,
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT IT WAS.
SO THIS MEATBALL--
NICE AND TENDER.
THE MARINARA IS ON POINT,
ESPECIALLY THE FRESH HERBS.
YEAH.
A LOT OF GARLIC,
A TOUCH OF THAT ANCHOVY
IN THERE. NICE JOB, MAN.
(speaking indistinctly)
MEATBALL SUB.
I LOVE THESE SANDWICHES.
GOOD MARINARA SAUCE.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
VERY CHEESY.
SO WHEN YOU GUYS
TOOK IT OVER, YOU SAID,
"MOM, ONE OF THE THINGS
WE NEED TO DO--MAKE MEATBALLS
LIKE WE USED TO HAVE
WHEN WE WERE KIDS"
YEAH. WE MAKE THE PIZZA
LIKE THAT, TOO.
(Casey) WE MAKE
OUR OWN DOUGH.
LAY IT OUT,
FILL IT UP.
YEAH, TOMATO MIX
ON TOP.
WHOA. STUFFED
PIZZA, PLEASE.
LOOK AT THIS THING. MMM.
ROCK STAR, MAN.
THANKS, MAN.
IT'S PRETTY RIDICULOUS,
ACTUALLY.
IT IS RIDICULOUS.
OH, THANK YOU, KRISTY.
THEY'VE REALLY DONE A GREAT JOB.
TABLE TWO.
WE WERE REALLY HAPPY
WHEN THE KEHRERS
TOOK OVER THE STEER-IN, BECAUSE
THEY'RE FROM THE EAST SIDE.
SHRIMP'S GOIN' IN.
AND THEY KNOW
WHAT EAST-SIDERS LIKE.
IT LOOKS DELICIOUS.
HOME-STYLE COOKIN'.
(Kristy) FRIED CHICKEN.
THE BEST--
IT REALLY IS.
MEAT LOAF,
TABLE FIVE UP.
BEEF AND NOODLES.
I GREW UP EATIN'
JUST LIKE CASEY.
IT'S AN OLD
FAMILY RECIPE
PASSED ON A COUPLE
GENERATIONS.
AND NOW HE'S
PASSIN' IT ON.
SO THIS IS THE STOCK?
YEAH, WE MAKE OUR STOCK,
BUILD IT FROM THERE.
WE'RE GONNA ROAST
SOME BONES.
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS.
NICE. NOW WE HIT IT
WITH THE MIREPOIX.
BAKE IT FOR ABOUT
ANOTHER HOUR.
ALL THIS FOR WHAT?
FOR BEEF AND NOODLES.
WE DROP THE BONES
AND VEGETABLES.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO MAKE THIS?
MY MOTHER.
WHO MAKES IT BETTER NOW?
SHE PROBABLY STILL DOES.
A GALLON AND 1/2 OF WATER.
SMELLS GREAT.
PAN DRIPPINGS OUT OF THERE.
WE COOK THAT DOWN
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS.
STRAIN IT.
LET ME TASTE IT.
RIGHT.
THIS WHOLE INSIDE ROUND
IS GONNA GO FOR BEEF NOODLES?
YES.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE RUB--
DRY AU JUS, GRANULATED GARLIC,
AND A BIT OF WATER.
SO WE'RE MAKIN'
SOME GRAVY BASE.
PRETTY MUCH.
NOW YOU SLATHER
THAT ON?
YEAH.
LOOKS LIKE PUDDIN'--
SALTY, MEATY GRAVY PUDDING.
JUST KINDA RUB IT
IN THERE GOOD.
YOU'RE JUST MAKIN'
ME NERVOUS.
YOU'VE GOT BROWN,
SALTY GRAVY,
AND I'VE GOT A LIGHT BLUE
HOSPITAL STRIPER OUTFIT ON.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
ON A BED OF MIREPOIX.
WRAP IT UP,
PUT IT DOWN,
ROAST IT OFF FOR AN HOUR AND
A HALF, COOK IT HALFWAY THROUGH.
THEN YOU TAKE THE COVER OFF IT.
IT COOKS DOWN.
LET IT BROWN UP EVEN MORE,
AND THEN WE'LL LET IT COOL.
WE'LL CUT THIS--
WE CUT IT
IN STRIPS LIKE THIS.
SHOULD WE CUT A LITTLE PIECE
OFF THE SIDE, AND...
YEAH, WE BETTER
TRY IT.
TRY IT?
LOOK AT THAT.
UH-HUH. MM-MMM.
THEN WE'LL GO AHEAD AND CUBE IT.
AND NOW IT GOES IN THE POT.
SO AS THAT
COOKS DOWN...
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME NOODLES.
FOUR EGG YOLKS,
TWO WHOLE EGGS,
OLIVE OIL, AND SALT.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
FRESH NOODLES.
LIKE SPAETZLE.
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR, OUR EGGS.
WHISK IT LIKE A BISCUIT.
KNEAD IT INTO A BALL.
AND WE KNEAD--
ABSOLUTELY.
JUST LIKE PASTA DOUGH. RIGHT,
SO THEY'VE HAD A CHANCE TO REST.
PUT A LITTLE FLOUR DOWN.
ROLL OUT THE DOUGH,
JUST LIKE MOM USED TO DO. USE
THE PIZZA ROCKER FOR CUTTING,
A COUPLE CHOPS THIS WAY.
JUST KINDA FLUFF IT ALL UP.
PUT IT INTO THE POT.
YOU COOK THE NOODLES
ACTUALLY IN THAT BROTH?
WE COOK THE NOODLES
IN EVERYTHING, YEAH.
THEY THICKEN IT UP. WE COOK
THAT DOWN FOR 45 MINUTES,
UNTIL THE NOODLES
ARE READY.
WAIT A SECOND, WE'RE SERVIN' UP
THE STARCHY PASTA WITH POTATOES?
WE ARE, YEAH. PROBABLY
AN INDIANA THING THERE.
I GUESS.
SO WE'RE READY.
OOH. PRETTY MUCH GOING ON
THE HOT SIDE, DON'T YOU THINK?
PRETTY MUCH.
MM-HMM.
I MEAN, THAT'S JUST GOOD OLD
STICK TO YOUR RIBS.
YEAH.
NOODLES ARE TENDER, GRAVY'S
RICH, MEAT JUST FALLS APART.
MMM. I THINK WHAT'S
REALLY IMPRESSIVE,
YOU ROAST OFF THE BONES,
MAKE THE AU JUS,
TURN OUT THE NOODLES.
I'LL BE BACK FOR THIS.
BEEF AND NOODLES.
I THINK THAT MEAT'S
BEEN COOKING ALL DAY.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT
GOOD AND MOIST AND TENDER.
I LOVE DOUBLE STARCH.
♪ AH ♪
WOW!
SHE LOVES
THE DOUBLE STARCH.
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
THIS IS THE OLD DINER.
THIS IS THE OLD
HANGOUT?
THIS IS IT, MAN.
WHAT A COOL THING,
TO GET IT.
YEAH, IT WAS NEAT TO SAVE IT
FROM GOING AWAY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
NICE PLACE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANKS SO MUCH.
VERY HAPPY FOR YOU. GOTTA COME
CHECK THESE GUYS OUT.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADING
OUTSIDE PHILADELPHIA...
EVERYTHING THEY'RE
DOING IS RIGHT.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
BOWL OF SNAPPER SOUP.
SNAPPING TURTLE SOUP.
IT'S TURTLE TIME.
SO HERE I AM IN THE CENTER
OF BUCKS COUNTY, P.A.
NOW FOR EVERYONE FROM
PENNSYLVANIA, NEW YORK,
AND NEW JERSEY,
YOU KNOW WHERE THAT IS.
BUT FOR A GUY FROM CALIFORNIA,
I'LL JUST SAY I'M, UH,
30 MILES NORTH OF PHILADELPHIA,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
IN A BUILDING FROM 1742,
AND TO TRY SOME OF THEIR
SNAPPING TURTLE SOUP.
THIS IS PINEVILLE TAVERN.
SNAPPER SOUP UP.
IT'S GREAT.
VERY UNIQUE TASTING SOUP.
SNAPPER SOUP.
IT'S ACTUALLY MADE
FROM SNAPPING TURTLE.
NOT SOMETHING YOU'D GET
IN SOUP EVERY DAY.
BUT YOU CAN GET IT
EVERY DAY HERE,
'CAUSE IT'S A LOCAL FAVORITE.
I LOVE IT.
SERIOUSLY?
JUST DON'T CALL IT
TURTLE SOUP.
TURTLE SOUP'S
FROM LOUISIANA.
OKAY.
THIS IS PENNSYLVANIA
SNAPPER.
GET IT STRAIGHT.
AND DREW ABRUZZESE
OUGHT TO KNOW...
MUSSELS WHITE
OVER LINGUINI.
HIS DAD ANDREW
OWNS THE JOINT...
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
AND DREW'S BEEN WORKING HERE
SINCE HE WAS 6.
SCRUBBING POTS,
WASHING DISHES.
AND PICKING TURTLE.
LET'S GET OUR TURTLE ON.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH A SPICE MIX.
SAVORY.
ANISE.
I SEE SOME CORIANDER, ALLSPICE,
LITTLE BROKEN UP BAY LEAF.
SAGE, CLOVE.
AND JUNIPER.
THIS MAKES A TEA.
NOW HOW LONG
WILL THIS STEEP?
30 TO 40 MINUTES, THEN
WE'RE JUST GONNA STRAIN IT.
SO THE TEA IS DONE,
AND NOW?
GONNA MAKE
THE SNAPPER STOCK.
BUTTER, CHOPPED CELERY.
SO A LITTLE
MIREPOIX GOING.
SWEAT THE VEGGIES DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
PRETTY SIMPLE SOUP.
SO FAR.
WHOA.
THAT'S FREAKY.
YEAH.
THIS IS ALL EDIBLE TURTLE?
ABSOLUTELY. THIS IS WHERE MOST
OF THE MEAT COMES FROM HERE,
IN THE SHOULDERS AND THE LEGS.
NOW WE'LL LOWER IN THE TURTLE.
NOT A SCENE THAT YOU SEE
EVERY DAY ON TRIPLE "D."
NOW THE TEA.
AND NOW WATER.
NOW IT COOKS FOR 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR,
GET THAT TURTLE MEAT
NICE AND TENDER.
IT'S... READY?
COOKED AND COOLED,
RIGHT IN THE PAN.
I'M AFRAID TO ASK,
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA PICK THE TURTLE
OUT OF THE SHELL.
LET'S GO IN
UNDERNEATH.
WHOA, YEAH!
SHELL'S OFF.
IT'S LIKE HE TORE OFF THE ROOF
OF A MINIVAN.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS
THE BREASTPLATE HERE.
COMES OFF.
WOW, IT'S LIKE RUBBER.
AND YOU WANT TO TRY AND LEAVE IT
AS CHUNKY AS POSSIBLE,
'CAUSE WE CAN ALWAYS MAKE IT
SMALLER LATER, BUT, UH,
RUSTIC IS WHAT
YOU'RE GOING FOR.
MM-HMM.
WHERE WE AT?
PUTTING THE SOUP TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME BUTTER, 2 POUNDS,
CARROTS, CELERY...
CELERY.
ONION...
ONIONS.
A LITTLE MIREPOIX. SWEAT
THE VEGETABLES A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A ROUX.
GO TO THE FLOUR.
WE'LL ADD IN THE SNAPPER STOCK,
TOMATO JUICE, DRY SHERRY,
AND YOU WANT TO GIVE IT
A NICE HARD WHISK.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD WATER...
WORCESTERSHIRE.
CAYENNE PEPPER,
WHITE PEPPER, NUTMEG.
CINNAMON?
CIM-A-NIN, SALT.
AND THIS?
KITCHEN BOUQUET.
NOW WE'LL BRING IT UP
TO A SIMMER.
ADD THE...
(whistles)
IN GOES THE TURTLE MEAT.
CHICKEN OF THE SWAMP.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
THE PADDLE, NOT THE WHISK,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT TO BREAK
UP THE MEAT TOO MUCH.
NO, WE DON'T.
SO WE'LL JUST BRING THAT
BACK UP TO A SIMMER,
AND THEN WE TURN IT OFF
AND SERVE IT.
IT'S TURTLE TIME.
COUPLE DASHES OF THAT.
WHAT IS THIS?
DRY SHERRY.
VERY NICE.
CHUNKY.
MMM. THE TURTLE'S
A LITTLE CHEWY FOR ME,
BUT COME ON, IT'S A TURTLE.
GOT A NICE GRAVY TEXTURE TO IT.
I LOVE THE ALLSPICE.
I LOVE THE TEA THAT WAS MADE.
THAT'S THE BACKBONE,
AND I GOTTA TELL YOU,
I WALKED INTO THIS
A LITTLE FEARFUL,
BUT I WILL BE
VERY TRUE WITH YOU--
I LIKE THE SAVORINESS OF IT.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING TO TRY
SOMETHING A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT, WITHOUT QUESTION,
YOU'VE GOT TO TRY
THE SNAPPER SOUP. MMM.
SNAPPER SOUP.
IT'S AWESOME FLAVOR.
IT'S FANTASTIC FLAVOR,
CREAMY, CHOWDER-Y,
ESPECIALLY ON A COLD DAY.
EVERYTHING THEY'RE
DOING IS RIGHT.
GREEN PEAS
AND PROSCIUTTO UP.
YOU'RE JUST GETTING
THE FRESHEST INGREDIENTS.
MUSSELS RED.
COMES THROUGH
IN THE FLAVOR.
FROM PUB FOOD
THAT PACKS A PUNCH...
BUFFALO EGG ROLLS,
PICK UP.
THE HOT SAUCE IS HOMEMADE.
OUT OF THIS WORLD.
TO PINEVILLE TRADITION.
THERE'S YOUR
RICE PUDDING.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND A WHOLE HUNK OF THE MENU
THAT'S RIGHT OUT OF
THE ABRUZZESE FAMILY COOKBOOK.
HALF RAVIOLI, FULL RAVIOLI,
TWO MEATBALLS.
THEIR MEATBALLS AND THEIR
RAVIOLIS ARE JUST TO DIE FOR.
RIGATONI BOLOGNESE.
AUTHENTIC.
THE RECIPES CAME OVER
FROM THE OLD COUNTRY.
THEY WERE BROUGHT OVER BY
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER CLARA.
RIGATONI BOLOGNESE, UP.
MY AUNTS MADE RAVIOLI
FOR CHURCH DINNERS.
AND IT JUST GETS PASSED DOWN
THROUGH THE GENERATIONS...
HALF RAVIOLI.
AND NOW I'M THE FOURTH
GENERATION IN AMERICA
MAKING THESE RAVIOLI.
TAKE ME TO FLAVOR TOWN,
SON.
WE USE 1/3, 1/3, 1/3,
BEEF, VEAL, AND PORK.
NICE AND HOT.
REALLY BREAK
THIS MEAT APART.
WE DON'T WANT
ANY BIG CHUNKS.
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU KNOW WHAT? YOU JUST
DON'T SEE IT AT FAIRS ANYMORE,
MEAT POPS. NEXT?
MINCED SHALLOT,
MINCED GARLIC,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER...
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT OF GRANULATED
GARLIC. GIVE THAT A STIR
TO INCORPORATE--
JUST A LITTLE BIT,
THOUGH, NOT A LOT AT ALL.
JUST A LITTLE BIT. THERE'S ALSO
GARLIC IN THE MARINARA SAUCE.
GOT IT.
LET IT COOL DOWN BEFORE WE MIX
IT WITH THE CHEESE FILLING.
ABSOLUTELY.
DIG IT. NOW WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT FILLING.
THAT'S MOUNT VESUVIUS
OF RICOTTA.
YOU CAN NEVER HAVE TOO MUCH
CHEESE. ABOUT A DOZEN EGGS.
PART SKIM MOZZARELLA CHEESE,
GRATED LOCATELLI ROMANO,
CHOPPED FLAT-LEAF PARSLEY, SALT,
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
SWITCH IT ON.
TWO TO THREE MINUTES.
MIX IT WITH THE MEAT.
PRECISE MEASUREMENT HERE?
VERY PRECISE--
RIGHT ABOUT THERE.
NOW WE'LL COMBINE THAT.
THAT IS GREAT, MAN.
THANK YOU.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE FINISHING THESE BABIES
OFF WITH SOME CULINARY KARATE.
ON TRIPLE "D."
WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE AT PINEVILLE TAVERN,
AND WE ARE ABOUT--WELL,
YOU'VE SEEN EVEL KNIEVEL
JUMP SNAKE RIVER.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THIS.
WE'RE MAKING RAVIOLIS.
THAT'S WHAT FOLKS
ARE PILING IN FOR...
I'M VERY HAPPY
WITH MY RAVIOLI.
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
FROM A FAMILY RECIPE...
HALF RAVIOLI.
THEY WERE BROUGHT OVER BY
MY GREAT-GRANDMOTHER CLARA.
AND DECADES LATER...
RAVIOLI, UP.
GREAT-GRANDSON DREW ABRUZZESE
IS THE ONE CRANKIN' 'EM OUT.
SO WE'RE SET WITH THE MEAT
FILLING FOR THE RAVS.
YEP.
NOW WAS THIS HAMMERED OUT
BY PAUL REVERE?
WE FOUND IT IN THE BASEMENT,
SO YOU NEVER KNOW.
NO, YOU DON'T.
INTO THE PIPING BAG.
AND THE DOUGH IS AS SIMPLE
AS SIMPLE GETS.
IT'S FLOUR AND EGGS.
IT'S LIKE MUSIC
TO MY EARS.
WE'LL MIX IT
FOR THREE MINUTES.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
OKAY, SO THE DOUGH'S
HAD A CHANCE TO REST,
AND NOW WE'LL SHEET THE PASTA,
MAKE THE RAVIOLIS.
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL SO SIMPLE.
GET THAT STARTED.
AND THE THICKNESS
ON THIS HAPPENS TO BE 7.
SO LOTS OF FLOUR
SO IT DOESN'T STICK AND BIND.
WE'LL GO AGAIN,
DROP IT DOWN ONE SETTING.
NOW THIS WILL BE
THE TRIPLE?
THIS WILL BE
THE TRIPLE HERE.
DOING THE TRIPLE
TO GET IT TO THE RIGHT SIZE
SO IT'LL GO THROUGH.
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
MORE FLOUR,
ONE SETTING LESS AGAIN.
NUMBER 3, 2,
WE'RE GOING DOWN TO 1.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S CRAZY.
FILLING'S
IN THE PIPING BAG,
STRAIGHT UP AND DOWN.
ROLL IT OVER.
NOW THE OTHER HALF.
STRAIGHT WITH THE LEFT,
CUP WITH THE RIGHT.
WHAT IS THIS,
"KARATE KID"?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
LOOKS GREAT.
THIS...
OKAY, CUT THEM, SEAL THEM,
AND FOR THAT,
WE USE OUR FORK.
THAT, WITHOUT QUESTION,
IS THE ULTIMATE
RAVIOLI TOOL.
WE HAD ONE MADE
FOR YOU.
DUDE!
JUST PRESS TO SEAL,
AND THAT'S IT.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP,
BOSS?
GET 'EM IN THE WATER.
NOW WE'RE JUST WAITING
TO COOK THE PASTA DOUGH ITSELF.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN
ON THE MARINARA.
IT'S VERY BASIC.
OLIVE OIL, GARLIC, AND CANNED
ITALIAN PLUM TOMATOES.
SAN MARZANO?
SAN MARZANO.
MMM.
AND RIGHT ON
TO THE PLATE.
LOOK AT THAT.
TOUCH IT UP WITH A LITTLE
FRESH CHOPPED PARSLEY,
AND SOME GRATED
LOCATELLI ROMANO.
NOW THAT'S A FORK.
MMM. THAT IS ALL THRILLA,
NO FILLA.
YOU'VE GOT THE BALANCE--
EXACT AMOUNT OF CREAMINESS.
YOU TASTE THE TEXTURE
IN THE RICOTTA STILL,
THEN YOU GET THE TEXTURE
IN THE MEAT,
AND THE FLAVOR'S
RIGHT ON POINT WITH IT.
THE MARINARA ADDS THAT ACID,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT STING
FROM SOME OF THAT CHEESE
RIGHT ON TOP OF IT.
HERE, YOU WANT
TO TRY SOME?
OH, I'M SORRY.
(woman) HOMEMADE
CHEESE RAVIOLI.
IT'S SO NICE AND THIN AND FRESH
AND DELICIOUS AND LIGHT.
THAT'S HOW YOU REALLY TELL
THAT IT'S HOMEMADE RAVIOLI.
(man) CHEESE RAVIOLI.
AND THE SAUCE
IS PERFECTION.
(woman) MUSSELS AND LINGUINI.
THERE'S A LOT OF THINGS THAT
PEOPLE TAKE PRIDE IN DOING,
AND THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT
EXTRA SPECIAL.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
LIKE HOME.
HOW'S EVERYONE
ENJOYING THINGS?
YOU GET THAT FEELING
AS SOON AS YOU WALK IN.
HUGS AND KISSES,
AND THEY KNOW RIGHT AWAY
TO BRING MY GLASS
OF WINE.
I DIDN'T--
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT--
I GOT NO HUG, NO KISS,
AND NO WINE.
I HAD TO CLEAN
THE TURTLE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OKAY.
I'M HERE IN
LANDMARK, SACRAMENTO,
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT,
AND THE STEAK SANDWICHES
AT JAMIE...
(laughs)