HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(man) THERE YOU GO.
FROM MOZZ...
(woman) MOZZARELLA STICKS.
TO MATZO BALLS.
MMM, THIS IS KILLER.
IN WILLISTON PARK, NEW YORK...
FROZEN HOT CHOCOLATE.
THANK YOU.
THE 1920s LANDMARK...
THIS IS ALL HOMEMADE.
THAT'S SERVING UP...
THE BUTTER PECAN
IS MY FAVORITE.
A BLAST FROM THE PAST.
MMM. TIMELESS.
IN SONOMA, CALIFORNIA...
THIS IS THE PERFECT
WINE COUNTRY RESTAURANT.
THE LOCAL CAFé...
SUNFLOWER WEDGE
IS READY.
DOING LAMB BURGERS...
SMELLS KILLER.
WITH A TWIST.
MMM. FEELING A LITTLE FLAVOR
BOOSTER FROM THAT CHIMICHURRI.
FROM THAT CHIMICHURRI.
AND IN DENVER, COLORADO...
PASTRAMI COMIN' UP.
IT'S JUST
THE BEST IN TOWN.
THE 44-YEAR-OLD JEWISH DELI...
THE TRADITION'S
CARRIED ON.
IT HASN'T CHANGED
AT ALL.
WHERE FAMILY FAVORITES
MEAN MATZO BALL SOUP...
THE BROTH IS WONDERFUL.
AND A TRIPLE "D" FIRST...
THERE'S THE KISHKE.
I GET A KICK
OUT OF KISHKE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW,
BEING FROM CALIFORNIA,
I ALWAYS DIG LEARNING ABOUT
THE HISTORY OF THE EAST COAST.
SO HERE I AM TO CHECK OUT
A PLACE IN WILLISTON PARK
ON LONG ISLAND.
NOW BACK IN 1927
WHEN THEY STARTED MAKING
CANDY AND ICE CREAM,
THEY WERE SURROUNDED
BY FARMLAND.
WELL, A LOT HAS CHANGED
SINCE THEN,
BUT THESE FOLKS
STAY THE SAME.
THIS IS HILDEBRANDT'S.
THERE'S YOUR
HOT FUDGE SUNDAE.
THANK YOU.
I WALK INTO THIS PLACE,
AND I'M A KID AGAIN.
THERE'S YOUR
BANANA SPLIT.
IT'S GOT THE OLD-FASHIONED
FEEL WITH A SODA COUNTER.
CHERRY LIME SODA.
BRINGS BACK A LOT
OF MEMORIES OF GROWING UP.
FOR OWNER SUSAN STRANO ACOSTA,
TOO...
THERE'S YOUR BUTTER PECAN
ICE CREAM CONE. ENJOY.
'CAUSE THE JOINT'S BEEN
IN HER FAMILY SINCE 1974.
IT WAS IMPORTANT FOR US
TO HAVE THE LEGACY CONTINUE.
AND THAT MEANS ICE CREAM
MADE FROM SCRATCH.
FROZEN HOT CHOCOLATE.
THANK YOU.
THE ICE CREAM
IS REALLY DELICIOUS HERE.
THE BUTTER PECAN
IS MY FAVORITE.
CRANKED OUT JUST LIKE
THE OLD DAYS,
DOWN IN THE BASEMENT...
ALMOST 100 FLAVORS
OF ICE CREAM.
BY ICE CREAM MAKER
TOM BAUMAN.
THIS IS MY PASSION
RIGHT HERE.
DUDE, HOW OLD IS THIS
DOWN HERE?
SINCE 1927--NOTHING'S BEEN
REALLY DONE SINCE THE BEGINNING.
NO, GET OUT.
SOME BIG FLAMES.
THIS WHERE WE STAY WARM,
OR WE GONNA ACTUALLY COOK--
THIS IS WHERE WE'RE
GONNA COOK SOMETHING TODAY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BUTTER PECAN ICE CREAM.
LOOK AT THAT.
LET'S MELT SOME BUTTER,
AND ONCE THAT'S FULLY MELTED,
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME SUGAR
AND BROWN SUGAR.
YOU'RE ACTUALLY
GONNA WEIGH IT?
THIS I'LL WEIGH.
1 POUND, THEN ANOTHER POUND
OF BROWN SUGAR.
THAT'S IT?
FOR 5 GALLONS.
PUT THAT RIGHT IN THERE,
A LITTLE MILK IN THERE.
DIET ICE CREAM.
WE JUST WANT TO MIX THIS UP,
POUR IT INTO A CONTAINER.
MAKES IT LOOK
SO EASY.
THAT'S IT. NOW WE GO IN
TO MAKE SOME ICE CREAM.
I'M GONNA FIRE
THIS UP.
(engine turns over)
DIDN'T THAT
SCARE YOU?
GONNA ADD THE BASE
THAT CONSISTS OF MILK,
SUGAR, AND CREAM--
NOTHING UNNATURAL
AT ALL.
EVERY ICE CREAM STARTS
WITH THAT--
STARTS WITH THAT BASE.
I'M GONNA ADD
WHAT WE JUST MADE, AND NOW--
RIGHT IN.
THE PECANS,
RIGHT IN THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
Of THE PECANS.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE
UNTIL IT FREEZES?
EIGHT TO TEN
MINUTES.
WE ARE READY.
LET THE FLOODGATES
COME OUT.
THAT'S CRAZY.
SWAP SPOON.
NICE AND LIGHT AND FLUFFY.
TONS OF CREAM TO IT.
SWAP SPOON.
MMM. I HAD TO TASTE IT
AT THE DIFFERENT STAGES.
POP IT IN THE FREEZER?
12 TO 24 HOURS,
IT'S GONNA BE READY
TO SERVE.
I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THAT FROZEN.
SO I'M GONNA BRING THIS
UPSTAIRS,
AND I'LL MEET YOU
UP THERE.
YOU'RE GONNA GO
WITH IT?
I'M GOIN' WITH IT.
THIS I GOTTA SEE.
THAT WAS WEIRD.
SO BUTTER PECAN.
LET'S GRAB OURSELVES
A GLASS.
I CAN HAVE IT IN A CONE
IF I WANT, RIGHT?
CAN HAVE A CONE.
YOU WANT A CONE?
NO, I WANT A GLASS.
OKAY.
THAT STUFF FREEZES UP.
LET'S GET THAT
PACKED IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME
WHIPPED CREAM ON THERE.
THIS IS HOMEMADE
WHIPPED CREAM.
REALLY?
CHERRY ON TOP,
BUTTERSCOTCH.
YOU MAKE
THE BUTTERSCOTCH?
YES, I DO.
IT'S GONNA GO ON THE SIDE.
WE DON'T WANT TO MELT
THE ICE CREAM.
MMM.
BUTTER PECAN.
CAN I ORDER THIS
IN THE MAIL?
I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'LL MAKE IT.
HANDMADE ICE CREAM, MMM,
TONS OF...
THE WHIPPED CREAM
IS OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
THE BUTTERSCOTCH--
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. NOTHING ARTIFICIAL.
NOTHING ARTIFICIAL
AT ALL.
MMM. TIMELESS.
HERE YOU GO.
BUTTER PECAN.
THANK YOU.
ENJOY.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING
RIGHT THERE?
I AM HAVING BUTTER PECAN
ICE CREAM.
OHH.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU
BEEN COMING HERE?
I GREW UP IN THIS AREA,
SO MANY YEARS.
WE'D COME TO HILDEBRANDT'S
FOR MILKSHAKES AND HAMBURGERS
EVERY FRIDAY NIGHT.
AND YOU STILL CAN, 'CAUSE
SUSAN AND HER HUSBAND BRYAN...
CAN I PLEASE HAVE A SIDE
OF FRIED ONION?
HAVE KEPT ALL
THE HILDEBRANDT'S TRADITIONS.
HERE YOU GO, DOC.
BOY, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
AND THEN SOME...
PASTA ASIAGO.
LIKE THE ITALIAN FAMILY
FAVORITES SUSAN'S PARENTS
BROUGHT TO THE TABLE
MORE THAN 30 YEARS AGO.
I KNOW GOOD ITALIAN COOKING.
IT'S REAL OLD-FASHIONED FOOD.
FROM PASTA A LA MAMA
WITH FRESH CAULIFLOWER...
JUST A BUNCH OF LOVE.
TO THE RIGATONI BUONGUSTO.
IT'S RIGATONI
DELICIOUS.
EVEN HOMEMADE
MOZZARELLA STICKS.
REALLY FRESH, CRISPY.
MARINARA SAUCE IS FANTASTIC.
AND EVEN THOUGH SUSAN'S MOM
JOANNE CLAIMS TO BE RETIRED...
I NEED A COUPLE
OF BAKED ZITIS, PLEASE.
YOU MIGHT STILL FIND HER
COOKING UP A BATCH.
SO WE'RE MAKING
THE MARINARA SAUCE, RIGHT?
YES,
FOR THE MOZZARELLA STICKS.
FIRST THE ONION,
ADD OREGANO AND SOME GARLIC.
SOME GARLIC.
FRESH CHOPPED. WE BLEND THIS.
IT'S LIKE
"TEXAS CHAINSAW MASSACRE."
GONNA PUT A LITTLE OIL IN THIS
JUST TO GET IT MOVIN'.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
AND THEN WE'LL DO THE SAME
WITH THE CELERY.
YES, WE ARE.
FRESH-CUT CELERY.
YES, IT IS.
AND THAT'S
THE SWEETNESS.
WE ADD SOME WATER.
BLEND IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA SAUTé THE ONIONS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA POP OVER--
BIG POT, TOMATO PURéE.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
I PUT IT IN THE BOWL,
I BRING IT TO YOU.
I'LL SLAM IT DOWN,
YOU CAN, BRING IT. AAH!
WE'LL ADD SOME WATER.
(normal voice)
PRETTY SIMPLE MARINARA.
YES, IT IS. ONION.
CELERY PURéE.
WE'LL ADD GRATED CHEESE.
PECORINO ROMANO, OKAY.
SALT, GARLIC.
GRANULATED GARLIC
THIS TIME,
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
YES.
AND THAT'S IT.
AND HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK DOWN?
A COUPLE HOURS.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE WORKING ON?
FRIED MOZZARELLA?
YES, WE ARE.
YOU JUST TAKE ABOUT
THIS MUCH.
AND HOW MANY SLICES ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO GET OUT OF IT?
FIVE PER PORTION.
THERE WE GO. PROBABLY CHECK
THAT. QUALITY MOZZARELLA.
OKAY, THIS IS OUR
BREADCRUMBS.
OKAY.
WE ADD GRATED CHEESE.
PECORINO ROMANO AGAIN?
YES, IT IS.
SHEEP'S CHEESE.
OREGANO, BLACK PEPPER, PARSLEY,
THEN I JUST MIX THIS ALL UP.
GO.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GOOD.
OKAY.
WE'VE GOT SOME EGGS,
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
WHISK THESE UP. WE'RE GOOD.
NOW CHEESE.
FLOUR STICKS TO THE CHEESE,
THE EGG STICKS TO THE FLOUR.
EXACTLY.
NOW DO YOU DO WET AND DRY HAND,
OR DO YOU GET BOTH OF 'EM
TO CLUMPY
BIG OL' MONSTER FINGERS?
BIG OL' MONSTER FINGERS.
VERY NICE.
WE'LL DO LIKE THIS,
YOU ROLL IT.
YEAH, WE HAVE TO DO THIS
THREE TIMES.
BACK AND FORTH
THREE TIMES?
YES, WE DO.
OH, SO ONE STICK GETS
THREE DUNK-A-DUNKS?
YES, IT DOES.
THAT WAS THREE
DUNK-A-DUNKS.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
IS THE OIL AT?
350 OR SO.
OKAY.
JUST POP THESE IN,
COOK 'EM UP QUICK.
COOK IT FAST. IS THAT IT?
BOOM, BOOM? LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO PLATE UP.
THE MARINARA'S DONE,
OR THE GRAVY.
PUT A LITTLE GRAVY ON THIS,
AND WE ARE DONE.
NOW THE QUESTION IS,
HOW FAR CAN WE GO?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THAT'S 4 FEET AT LEAST.
MMM.
DIP IT IN THE SAUCE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I'M JUST TRYING
TO LASSO IN MY CHEESE. MMM.
GOOD CHEESE, SIMPLE MARINARA
MADE YOURSELF.
WHEN I THINK COMING
TO LONG ISLAND,
AND THE PLACE HAS BEEN HERE
SINCE 1927,
THIS IS WHAT I WOULD EXPECT
THEM TO BE LIKE. THANKS, JO.
MOZZARELLA STICKS.
GREAT, THANK YOU.
PERFECT TASTE FOR ME.
THIS MARINARA SAUCE--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THIS IS ALL HOMEMADE.
CHICKEN DAKOTA.
IT HAS A FLAVOR OF AN AGE
THAT'S ALREADY PASSED.
(man) BUTTERSCOTCH SUNDAE.
HAVE YOU HAD
THE ICE CREAM BEFORE?
OBVIOUSLY, OF COURSE.
OBVIOUSLY--I MEAN...
THAT'S A CRAZY QUESTION.
ARE YOU FROM
NOT AROUND HERE?
YEAH, I MEAN,
COME ON, MAN.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING
TO SONOMA, CALIFORNIA...
ROAST VEGGIE SALAD.
FOR BURGERS...
LAMB BURGERS UP.
AND BORSCHT.
VEGGIES ARE SO TENDER.
NOW I KNOW YOU'VE HEARD ME
SAY IT TIME AND TIME AGAIN,
I LIVE IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
IN THE WINE COUNTRY,
AND ONE OF THE MOST RECOGNIZED
TOWNS IN THE MIDDLE OF IT ALL
IS SONOMA, AND RIGHT
ON THE SQUARE IN SONOMA
IS A COOL LITTLE PLACE
THAT'S GOT GREAT SOUPS
AND KILLER SANDWICHES.
THIS IS THE SUNFLOWER CAFFé.
BOWL OF BORSCHT.
IT'S A HIDDEN TREASURE
HERE IN WINE COUNTRY.
I LOVE IT.
I COME HERE EVERY DAY. MMM.
WHITE BEAN ROASTED GARLIC SOUP--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
ROAST VEGGIE SALAD.
FRESH CHEESES
AND FRESH VEGETABLES.
GOAT CHEESE FILLED
PIQUILLO PEPPER.
I CAN'T SAY ENOUGH
ABOUT THE FOOD.
OR LONG-TIME CHEF
CURTIS DORSETT.
GOT YOUR CHIMICHURRI.
CURTIS IS A MASTER
IN THE KITCHEN.
HE'S GOTTA BE...
CUP OF BEEF BORSCHT UP.
THIS IS THE WHOLE STOVE
FOR THE WHOLE RESTAURANT?
I HAVE ANOTHER
ONE OF THESE.
OH, MY GOODNESS,
TWO OF THEM.
I HAVE NO BURNERS.
I DO EVERYTHING HERE
WITH SMOKE AND MIRRORS.
SMOKE AND MIRRORS?
AND A GRILL OUT BACK.
LAMB BURGERS UP.
A REALLY WONDERFUL,
FRESH TAKE ON A CLASSIC.
THEY ALWAYS HAVE A SPECIAL
INGREDIENT THAT COMPLETES
THE DISH, BUT YOU CAN'T QUITE
FIGURE OUT WHAT IT IS.
ON THE LAMB BURGER,
THAT WOULD BE THE HARISSA.
...WHICH IS A NORTH AFRICAN
SPICE MIX.
WE CAN'T GET THE KIND OF CHILIES
THAT THEY USE IN NORTH AFRICA,
SO I USE
A BLACK PASILLA PEPPER,
WHICH I TOAST
IN THE OVEN.
IT'S YOUR STYLE.
IT'S MY HARISSA.
SO THE TOASTED
PASILLA PEPPERS.
MY LITTLE
SPICE GRINDER HERE.
YOU'RE GOING SEEDS
AND ALL IN THERE?
I DEFINITELY WANT THE HEAT. WE
GET THAT ALL NICE AND GROUND UP.
PIQUILLO PEPPER--THE SWEET
FLAVOR, TOASTED CORIANDER.
YOU GOTTA TOAST
YOUR HERBS.
SEEDS AND NUTS--
IF THEY'RE NOT TOASTED...
YOU JUST DON'T REALLY GET ALL
THE GREAT FLAVOR THEY POSSESS.
ROASTED GARLIC,
TOMATO PASTE.
THERE WE ARE.
CUMIN, KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER IN THERE, TOO,
AND THE GROUND PASILLA,
A LITTLE SPIKE...
DUDE, YOU ARE ALL OVER
THE BOARD ON THIS.
SRIRACHA IN THERE.
GRIND THIS PUPPY UP.
YOU DIDN'T PUT ANY
PUPPY IN THERE, DID YOU?
A LITTLE OIL
IN THERE.
IT'S LIKE MAD SCIENTIST
BACK HERE.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S CHECK
TO SEE IF IT'S BALANCED.
OH.
KIND OF WILD, HUH?
KIND OF AWESOME.
TALK ABOUT GREAT, BIG FLAVOR.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA MAKE A 1, 2, 3,
4--15-INGREDIENT CHIMICHURRI.
YEAH. THIS SAUCE
IS PRETTY ACIDIC.
CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR,
SOME LEMON JUICE, DRY OREGANO.
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE
GARLIC IN THERE,
JALAPEÑOS--
GRIND ALL THIS UP.
SOME ITALIAN FLAT-LEAF PARSLEY
AND SOME CILANTRO.
CILANTRO.
I'M A BIG FAN OF THE GREEN
AND THE GARLIC, THE ACID.
I WANT TO TURN THIS
ALMOST INTO A PASTE.
OKAY. CHECK OUT
THE GREEN IN THAT.
LET THIS KIND OF STEEP IN
THE VINEGAR AND THE LEMON JUICE.
YELLOW ONION HERE.
SO THESE WILL GO IN HERE.
FRESH TOMATOES.
AND NOT DO IT ALL AT ONE TIME,
OR IT WON'T HOLD THE COLOR.
RIGHT.
REALLY?
THIS WILL MAKE IT
LIQUID-Y.
SEE HOW IT'S HOLDING
ITS GREEN COLOR,
EVEN THOUGH I PUT
ALL THAT RED IN THERE?
OH, YEAH.
SALT AND SOME OLIVE OIL,
AND, OF COURSE,
I HAVE TO TASTE IT
TO MAKE SURE IT'S RIGHT.
I'M IN THIS WITH YA.
MMM. NICE AND BRIGHT
AND FRESH AND VIBRANT.
CHIMICHURRI'S DONE. LAST THING
TO DO IS THE LAMB BURGER.
DOCTOR.
ALL RIGHT.
CRUMBLED FETA...
(whistles)
IN HERE.
SINCE WE HAVE TWO LITTLE
PROPANE BURNER STOVES,
THE MAGIC OVEN--
WHERE DOES THIS GET COOKED?
GETS COOKED
ON THE OUTDOOR GRILL.
LITTLE SPRINKLE
OF BLACK PEPPER ON HERE.
I'M GONNA RUB IT
WITH THIS HARISSA.
NICE COLOR ON THAT.
THAT'S IT.
LET'S GO
TO THE GRILL.
OUR BURGER GOES ON.
I LIKE MY BURGER MEDIUM-RARE.
SOUNDS FANTASTIC. THAT FETA
WITH THE LAMB RIGHT THERE.
OH, THAT SMELLS KILLER.
READY?
I THINK WE'RE
LOOKING READY.
LITTLE CHIMICHURRI
ON THE TOP.
THERE WE HAVE IT--
OUR LAMB BURGER.
HERE WE GO.
OKAY. JUST LOOK
AT THE JUICE ON THIS.
MMM. YOU GET ALL THAT GREAT,
STRONG, BRINY FLAVOR
OF THE FETA, THAT BUTTERINESS
THAT YOU GET OF THE LAMB--
MMM--A LITTLE FLAVOR BOOSTER
FROM THAT CHIMICHURRI...
FROM THAT CHIMICHURRI.
MMM--THAT'S LIKE
THE LUSCIOUS LAMB BURGER.
MMM. MM-MM-MMM.
SERIOUSLY, ONE OF THE BEST
YOU'LL TRY.
HERE'S YOUR LAMB BURGER
FOR YOU.
REALLY SAVORY, JUICY,
A LOT OF FETA INSIDE OF IT.
THE CHIMICHURRI HELPS
BALANCE EVERYTHING OUT.
EVERYTHING HAS WONDERFUL,
BURSTING FLAVORS.
THAI CURRY AND PORK SOUP
IS READY.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
WHO HAD THE ROAST VEGGIE
SALAD?
ME.
SEASONED PERFECTLY,
AND THEY HAVE A GREAT VARIETY.
MMM. YOU KNOW,
THE PLACE IS SPECIAL.
THIS IS A GO-TO?
YEAH.
AND THE NEW WINE BAR--
IT GETS BETTER AND BETTER
ALL THE TIME.
THANKS TO NEW OWNER...
HEY, GUYS,
HOW ARE YOU?
JAMES HAHN.
MY DAD WAS A FARMER.
MAKING GRAPES FOR OTHERS.
WHAT A BETTER WAY TO CARRY ON
MY DAD'S TRADITION
THAN TO HAVE
A WINE BAR?
GREAT WINE LIST.
STOCKED WITH FAVORITES
STRAIGHT OUT OF SONOMA.
HOW'S THE WINE?
LOCALLY GROWN
IS A BIG THING UP HERE.
IN EVERYTHING THEY DO...
DUCK BREAST SANDWICH.
LOCAL DUCK.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THERE'S YOUR
BEEF BORSCHT.
ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
FRESH LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
CABBAGE AND BEETS
WITH ROASTED MEATS
AND A DOLLOP OF SOUR CREAM--
THAT'S ALL RIGHT WITH YOU?
OH, IT'S GREAT.
START ME OFF.
HOW DO WE DO IT?
I START WITH
CHICKEN STOCK.
GOT MY BEETS.
SO JUST RAW BEETS THAT HAVE
BEEN PEELED AND CHOPPED.
I LIKE TO LEAVE THEM CHUNKY.
CABBAGE IS IMPORTANT ALSO.
SOME CELERY.
YOU NEED THAT
NATURAL SUGAR.
ONIONS.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
I LIKE IT.
ALL GONNA GO IN HERE
TOGETHER. POTATOES IN HERE.
AND WHERE'S EVERYTHING ELSE
GONNA FIT IN THIS?
THE CABBAGE IS GONNA
REALLY COOK DOWN A LOT,
AND GIVE ME SPACE IN THERE.
GROUND TOASTED CARAWAY SEEDS.
VERY NICE.
SOME GARLIC,
SALT, AND PEPPER.
AND SOME DILL.
SO THIS WILL JUST SIT AND--
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK DOWN?
PROBABLY ABOUT
15 MINUTES.
WHILE THIS IS COOKING...
WE'RE GONNA SEASON
THE BEEF.
SALT, PEPPER.
WE'RE JUST GONNA MIX THIS UP.
AND WHAT ARE WE USING?
THIS IS STEW MEAT.
CHUCK TO SIRLOIN
TO FILET MIGNON.
YEAH.
DIG IT. SO GONNA POP THIS
IN THE LITTLE OVEN.
AT ABOUT 400.
PUT A LITTLE SEAR
ON THE MEAT.
IT'S ALL NICE
AND BROWNED UP,
AND IT'S ACCUMULATED
SOME BEEFY JUICES.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE
ALL THAT MAKES IT INTO THE POT.
OH, BOY.
KEY COMPONENT.
WE'RE GONNA SIMMER THIS
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
THAT'S SOME GOOD LOOKING
FOCACCIA.
WE HAVE OUR
FINISHED SOUP HERE.
NICE AND DONE.
SOME SOUR CREAM,
WHICH I THINK IS REALLY
IMPORTANT TO THIS SOUP.
SO THERE YOU GO.
OH.
HMM.
THAT IS SERIOUSLY KILLER.
THE VEGGIES ARE SO TENDER.
OH, MAN.
IT'S THAT CARAWAY, THAT DILL
BITE THAT YOU GET IN THERE.
ALL THOSE BIG FLAVORS
THAT ARE COMING OUT,
PICKING UP SOME OF THE SOUR
CREAM--OH, THAT'S GREAT.
NICE JOB. I CAN'T
GET IT IN FAST ENOUGH.
IT'S REALLY SWEET
FROM THE BEETS,
AND RICH FROM THE BEEF.
CUP OF BEEF BORSCHT UP.
THE BEEF IS COOKED
PERFECTLY.
THIS IS A FUN PLACE
TO COME.
HOW'S EVERYTHING
OVER HERE?
IT'S ALWAYS ON POINT.
ALWAYS ON POINT.
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS THE PERFECT
WINE COUNTRY RESTAURANT.
THERE'S YOUR
LAMB BURGER. ENJOY.
IS IT TRUE THAT YOU'RE
REALLY THINKING ABOUT
NAMING THIS PLACE--BE HONEST--
THE LUSCIOUS LAMB BURGER CAFE?
(laughs) YEAH.
IS THAT WHAT YOU GUYS WERE
THINKING ABOUT CALLING IT?
'CAUSE IF YOU WERE--
YEAH, THE SECRET'S OUT,
YEAH.
CONGRATULATIONS.
EXCELLENT.
NEXT STOP...
JUMBO BRISKET
ON PUMPERNICKEL.
WE'RE HEADING TO DENVER...
IT'S JUST THE BEST
IN TOWN.
FOR MILE-HIGH
MATZO BALLS...
THE FLAVOR
IS OUTRAGEOUS. MMM.
WHEN I SEE DENVER, COLORADO,
WHAT COMES TO MIND?
WELL, DEFINITELY THE BRONCOS
AND MILE HIGH STADIUM
AND THE GATEWAY TO GREAT SKIING,
BUT DO YOU THINK JEWISH DELI?
YOU KNOW, MAKING THE MATZO BALL
SOUP AND THE KNISHES?
WELL, YOU MAY NOT
HAVE THOUGHT IT BEFORE,
BUT THAT COULD ALL CHANGE TODAY,
'CAUSE WE'RE HERE TO CHECK OUT
THE BAGEL DELI & RESTAURANT.
JUMBO BRISKET
ON PUMPERNICKEL.
TREMENDOUS.
(woman) HERE'S
THE MATZO BALL SOUP.
I LOVE IT.
IT'S JUST THE BEST
IN TOWN.
PASTRAMI COMIN' UP.
IS THIS REAL-DEAL
JEWISH FOOD?
OH, YEAH.
IT'S TRADITION.
STARTED BY RHODA KAPLAN'S
PARENTS 44 YEARS AGO.
THERE'S YOUR KISHKE.
AND PROUDLY CONTINUED
BY RHODA...
I NEED THE AU JUS.
AND HER HUSBAND JOE.
GOT A TONGUE SANDWICH UP.
AND THE TRADITION'S
CARRIED ON.
IT HASN'T CHANGED AT ALL.
'CAUSE RHODA STILL USES
HER BUBBY'S RECIPES...
BUBBY IS GRANDMA.
BUBBY MEANS
GRANDMOTHER.
LIKE THIS BUBBY'S CLASSIC...
MATZO BALL SOUP.
ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
THAT RHODA'S BEEN MAKING
SINCE SHE WAS 3 YEARS OLD.
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
(whistles)
EGGS, WHITE PEPPER, GINGER.
ARE MATZO BALLS
ALWAYS WITH GINGER?
THEY SHOULD BE.
SALT, OIL--
MIX THIS REAL GOOD.
OKAY. VERY NICE.
♪ ROW, ROW,
ROW YOUR CHICKENS ♪
NOW MATZO MEAL. YOU HAVE
TO MIX REALLY CAREFULLY.
OR YOU'LL GET...
LUMPS.
INCONSISTENCY, CLUMP-AGE,
AND BREAK APART.
INCONSISTENCY, LUMPS.
THEN WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS GONNA TAKE IT,
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
INTO ANOTHER BOWL.
BECAUSE?
BECAUSE I LIKE THIS
LITTLE BOWL BETTER.
IT'S EASIER FOR ME TO ROLL
MY MATZO BALLS.
YOU JUST LIKE
DOING DISHES.
SO WE PUT THAT IN
THE REFRIGERATOR FOR HOW LONG?
FOUR TO FIVE HOURS.
SO IT'S CHILLED UP,
CONGEALED ENOUGH
THAT IT'LL
BE ABLE TO SCOOP.
CORRECT.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA ROLL
THE MATZO BALLS.
WE SCOOPED 'EM,
NOW WE HAVE TO ROLL 'EM?
CORRECT.
PUT YOUR HANDS IN OIL
LIKE THAT.
SMOOTHEN 'EM OUT.
THAT'S IT.
HOW LONG DO THEY TAKE
TO COOK?
ABOUT 35 MINUTES.
AND WHILE THOSE ARE COOKING,
WE START ON THE CHICKEN STOCK?
SURE.
OKAY.
KOSHER CHICKEN, CELERY,
CARROTS, ONIONS.
THEN I NEED YOUR HELP
FOR THAT WATER. PLEASE?
SEE? LUCKY I'M HERE.
AND IT'S ALREADY WARM.
THERE YOU GO.
PUT A LITTLE
FLARE ON IT.
IT'S GONNA COOK FOR ABOUT THREE,
THREE AND A HALF HOURS.
PULL OUR CHICKENS OUT, TAKE
THE VEGETABLES OUT SEPARATE.
THEN WHAT WE DO IS WE'LL TAKE
THREE QUARTERS OF THIS STOCK,
HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF A CHICKEN BASE, CARROTS.
YEP.
PUT IN THE CHICKEN
THAT WE SHREDDED, PARSLEY,
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
OKAY.
MIX 'EM UP,
AND WE'RE DONE.
DIG IT.
NOW WE TAKE THE MATZO BALLS.
SEE HOW BIG THEY GOT?
YEP. HOW MANY GALLONS
OF THIS DO YOU GO THROUGH?
15, 20 GALLONS A DAY.
WHAT?
I KNOW WHEN THERE'S
A FLU EPIDEMIC.
EVERYBODY COMES IN
FOR MATZO BALL SOUP.
MMM. THIS IS KILLER. THE MATZO
BALL IS SUPER LIGHT AND TENDER,
BUT HAS GREAT TEXTURE.
THE FLAVOR IS OUTRAGEOUS.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
MMM. I DON'T EVEN FEEL SICK,
AND I FEEL BETTER ALREADY.
GOOD.
MATZO BALL SOUP.
MATZO BALLS
ARE PERFECT.
THE BROTH IS WONDERFUL.
YOU JUST KNOW THAT
IT WAS MADE WITH CARE.
HERE'S YOUR CORNED BEEF
AND EGG SALAD.
THE FOOD
IS ABSOLUTELY TREMENDOUS.
JUMBO TURKEY.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
IT'S MADE WITH LOVE.
CHOPPED LIVER AND EGG SALAD.
WE LOVE YOU,
WE THINK ABOUT YOU.
GIVE RHODA A KISS.
I MISSED YOU.
WE JUST KNOW YOU,
AND WE TREAT YOU LIKE FAMILY.
AND IT'S BEEN LIKE THAT
FOR GENERATIONS.
MY GRANDMOTHER
STARTED THE TRADITION
WHERE WE ALL HAVE BRUNCH
ON SUNDAY.
EVERY SUNDAY?
EVERY SUNDAY.
WHEN YOU CAN GET
TWO OF BUBBY'S BEST...
BRISKET KNISHES HERE.
STUFF THAT YOU WANT...
WE HAVE SUCH
FABULOUS BRISKET,
WE DECIDED TO MAKE
A KNISH OUT OF IT.
IT'S A DELISH KNISH.
HEY, THAT'S GOOD.
OKAY, SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
HOW ARE WE DOING THIS?
FIRST OF ALL, WE'RE GONNA
TAKE THESE BRISKETS.
FAT UP, SO AS IT COOKS DOWN,
YOU RENDER DOWN THE FAT,
MOISTURIZES IT--GOT IT?
YOU GOT IT.
OKAY, FIRST IN?
CARROTS IN.
JUST WHOLE LIKE THAT?
WHOLE LIKE THAT.
CELERY IN--WHOLE LIKE THAT.
THEN WE PUT THESE LOVELY
PEELED YELLOW ONIONS IN.
THANK GOODNESS
WE CUT THE ONION--
I KNOW.
AT LEAST,
SEMI-CUT THE ONION.
NOW?
THE PEPPER, GARLIC POWDER.
YUMMY.
AND THEN THIS
IS AN AU JUS MIX.
BEEF BASE.
YEAH. WE JUST COVER IT
WITH WATER.
OKAY, SO EVERYBODY'S
IN THE POOL.
IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO COVER
IT REALLY, REALLY TIGHT.
GO TO THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP?
THIS GOES IN THE OVEN,
400, 5 1/2 HOURS.
CAN YOU GO GET
THE BRISKETS OUT FOR ME?
COME ON.
I KNOW. BE CAREFUL.
WHOA, OH, OH.
HOT, HOT, HOT, HOT, HOT.
JUICY, JUICY, JUICY,
JUICY, JUICY.
PERFECT.
THANKS, DEAR.
I BETTER GET
A HANUKKAH CARD.
TAKE THIS OFF.
WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM OVER HERE.
WE'RE GONNA DRAIN THIS STUFF,
'CAUSE WE'RE GONNA MAKE...
THE AU JUS.
USE AS A BASE
FOR OUR KISHKE.
LOOK AT THAT.
SMELLS AWESOME.
THAT'S GOOD.
TRIM THESE, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE MIX
FOR THE MEAT KNISHES
OUT OF THAT.
DON'T YOU THINK WE SHOULD
PICK AT IT AND EAT SOME FIRST?
WELL, YEAH.
REALLY NICE
BEEF FLAVOR.
CUT THIS INTO PIECES.
NOW THIS ALL GOES
IN THE BUFFALO CHOPPER?
MM-HMM.
GO. NOTHING LIKE
BIG KITCHEN EQUIPMENT.
THAT'S ABOUT THE CONSISTENCY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
TAKE THIS OUT OF HERE.
ON GOES THE GLOVES, 'CAUSE
THIS GETS KINDA MESSY NOW.
WHITE PEPPER, GARLIC,
SEASON-ALL, EGGS.
A LITTLE CHICKEN BINDER
THERE.
YEP.
SAUTéED ONIONS. SO THAT GETS
ALL MIXED UP REALLY GOOD.
AND THEN THESE
PASTRIES HERE?
PUT 'EM HERE IN THE MIDDLE,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PAINT.
OKAY.
THIS IS JUST EGGS AND MILK,
A LITTLE EGG WASH.
SCOOP IT IN,
BRING THE ENDS UP, TWIST IT...
OKAY.
SMASH IT, SO IT LOOKS
ABOUT LIKE THAT.
OH, WOW.
REALLY SMASH.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
PUT THIS ON THAT
COOKIE SHEET.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAME EGG WASH.
AND WE KNOCK OUT 50
OR 60 A DAY?
BAKE 'EM OFF AT WHAT,
350?
350 FOR ABOUT 35,
40 MINUTES.
AND THAT'S THE KNISH.
MMM.
SMELLS GOOD, HUH?
MMM. THAT'S GREAT.
GOOD.
NICE AND FLAKY,
NOT OVERLY SALTY. MMM.
SO THIS IS
RED HORSERADISH.
MMM!
GOOD STUFF,
THAT RED HORSERADISH, HUH?
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN
WITH THE PURPLE HORSERADISH
ALL MY LIFE?
THAT IS THE BITE RIGHT THERE,
WHEN YOU COMPLEMENT IT
WITH THE TWO--MMM.
NICE JOB.
BRISKET KNISHES UP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
CROISSANT ON STEROIDS.
JUST TASTES
LIKE HOME COOKING.
ROAST BEEF COMIN' UP.
YOU WALK IN HERE,
YOU KNOW EVERYBODY,
YOU'VE BEEN EATING THIS FOOD
SINCE YOU WERE A LITTLE KID.
FROM REUBEN...
IT'S VERY TASTY.
TO POTATO LATKES...
BEST IN THE WORLD.
AND SOMETHING
CALLED KISHKE...
RUSH ORDER
FOR YOUR KISHKE.
MADE WITH MATZO MEAL,
SPICES, AND SCHMALTZ...
THAT'S MELTED CHICKEN FAT.
CORRECT.
PUDDING CUP, KIDS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
I GET A KICK
OUT OF KISHKE.
AT THE BAGEL DELI & RESTAURANT
IN DENVER, COLORADO...
THE MATZO BALL SOUP.
OWNER RHODA KAPLAN...
GOT IT ALL?
THAT'S IT.
AND HER HUSBAND JOE...
BRISKET KNISHES HERE.
ARE SERVING UP
JEWISH TRADITION...
MATZO BALL SOUP.
AND A CLASSIC SOME FOLKS
HAVEN'T EVEN HEARD OF.
THERE'S THE KISHKE.
KIND OF LIKE STUFFING.
NEVER HAD THIS.
THIS TASTES LIKE A JEWISH
MEATLOAF. IT'S JUST FABULOUS.
DONE RHODA'S WAY.
OKAY, GO TO IT.
OKAY, YOU READY? WE'RE GONNA
TURN ON MY FAVORITE.
BUFFALO CHOPPER.
I LOVE THIS.
CARROTS WHOLE.
GET READY, YOU MIGHT CRY--
ONIONS.
I'VE SEEN THIS MOVIE BEFORE.
THIS HAS TO GRIND
FOR JUST A LITTLE BIT, OKAY?
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
WHITE PEPPER, POULTRY SEASONING,
PAPRIKA, AU JUS MIX,
GARLIC POWDER, KOSHER SALT.
MIX THAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'VE GOT EGGS.
OKAY.
MATZO MEAL, NOW THE FLOUR.
THIS IS
THE MELTED SCHMALTZ.
OOPS, SORRY.
GOT SCHMALTZ
ALL OVER ME!
SO THAT'S MELTED
CHICKEN FAT.
CORRECT.
CONVENIENTLY PACKED.
PUDDING CUP, KIDS.
OKAY, NOW WE ADD
THE OIL.
REGULAR CANOLA OIL.
REGULAR OL' CANOLA OIL.
SEE IF IT'S RIGHT.
IT'S GOTTA BE ABOUT
THAT CONSISTENCY.
AND WE'RE GOOD.
CAN YOU EAT IT NOW?
OH, YEAH.
YEAH, LET'S NOT.
UM, NOW WHAT'S UP?
YEARS AGO, YOU WOULD PUT IT
IN ACTUAL COW'S INTESTINE.
WE CALL THAT CASING.
YEAH.
BUT WE'RE NOT PUTTING IT
IN THE CASING.
NO.
TAKE A PIECE, MAKE IT
LOOK KIND OF LIKE A LOG...
WRAP IT UP IN TINFOIL.
AND ROLL IT
PRETTY DARN TIGHT.
TWIST ONE END,
TWIST ANOTHER END.
THEY'RE GONNA BAKE
FOR HOW LONG?
35 MINUTES,
TURN 'EM OVER,
AND THEN ABOUT
ANOTHER 35, 40 MINUTES.
THERE'S SCHMALTZ
ALL OVER THAT.
THERE IS SCHMALTZ
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS ONE,
WE'RE GONNA UNCOVER IT.
SO NOW YOU SEE WHY
YOU HAD TO TURN IT,
'CAUSE YOU DON'T WANT IT GETTING
TOO BURNT ON BOTH SIDES.
THIS IS CRAZY.
CUT IT...
UH-HUH.
PUT IT ON THERE.
THIS IS THAT YUMMY AU JUS
THAT WE MADE OUT OF THE BRISKET.
POUR THAT OVER IT.
IT'S ALL YOURS FOR THE TASTING.
MMM.
WHERE'S THIS BIG JEWISH
DUMPLING BEEN ALL MY LIFE?
LOOK AT THIS THING. MMM.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE SWEETNESS
FROM THE CARROT.
IT REALLY TAKES ON THE FLAVOR
OF THE CHICKEN STOCK.
IT'S LIKE A MATZO BALL
GONE WILD. I'M SURPRISED.
OUT OF ALL THE JEWISH DELIS
WE'VE SHOT ON TRIPLE "D,"
AND OF ALL THE JEWISH MEALS
I'VE ENJOYED,
I MEAN, KISHKE.
I GET A KICK
OUT OF KISHKE.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
NICE JOB.
THANKS.
KISHKE.
OH, THE KISHKE
IS SO GOOD.
IT'S VERY RICH.
TENDER AND MOIST.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
BAKED KNISHES
COMIN' UP.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS
CONSISTENTLY GREAT.
IT'S A VERY SPECIAL PLACE.
IT'S TOUGH TO BEAT.
PLAIN CORNED BEEF
COMIN' UP.
(Guy) CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS, THANKS.
AWESOME PLACE.
CHECK IT OUT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
AND THAT'S JUST ABOUT
THE SIZE YOU WANT.
WOW, WITH AUTHORITY.
I'M TELLIN' YA.
SEE THE POSE?
I DON'T MESS AROUND.
GAVE ME A LITTLE
HEISMAN ON THAT.