HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
NOT BAD, HUH...
NOT BAD.
FOR A ROOKIE.
FROM CREPES...
PESTO CHICKEN CREPE UP.
TO KREPLACH...
IT'S LIKE
A JEWISH EGG ROLL.
IN BOULDER, COLORADO...
EVERYTHING IS HOMEMADE.
THE FUNKY CAFE...
IT'S ALL GOOD.
WHERE THEY'RE
CRANKING OUT CREPES...
LOOKING GOOD.
MORE THAN 20 DIFFERENT WAYS...
BUTTER RUM CREPE CAKE.
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
IN QUEENS, NEW YORK...
THE FOOD'S TOP-NOTCH.
THE 1940s JEWISH DELI...
(woman) MATZO BALL.
SERVING UP ALL THE CLASSICS...
PASTRAMI SANDWICH.
FROM STUFFED CABBAGE...
IT TASTES
LIKE IT'S HOMEMADE.
TO KREPLACH...
MMM.
AND IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
THE FOOD IS PHENOMENAL.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD PUB...
THE MOST BEER ON TAP
IN SPOKANE.
WHERE IT'S BURGERS GONE WILD...
BIG DOG BURGER
WITH SWEET FRIES.
AMAZING.
AND A CHEESESTEAK TO MATCH.
(man) THIS IS
THE IRISH LAMB DIP.
RIGHT ON POINT.
I CAN CHUG THE AU JUS.
(laughs)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN BOULDER, COLORADO,
IN THE DOWNTOWN AREA
ABOUT A 5-MINUTE WALK NORTH
OF COLORADO UNIVERSITY.
NOW ON TRIPLE "D"
WE'VE CHECKED OUT JOINTS
FOR TORTILLAS, PIZZA, PASTA,
CHICKEN WINGS, CHEESESTEAKS,
I MEAN, YOU NAME IT,
BUT WE'VE NOT YET FOUND A JOINT
THAT'S BEEN ROCKIN' THE CREPE.
THAT'S UNTIL NOW.
THIS IS FOOLISH CRAIG'S.
FOOLISH CRAIG CREPE
IN THE WINDOW.
AND THERE IS A CRAIG...
FRUIT CREPE FOR YOU.
CRAIG MOELIS...
EGGPLANT FOR YOU.
WHO CAME UP WITH THE IDEA
WHEN HE AND HIS PAL MITCH ARDEN
WERE WORKING ACROSS TOWN
AT A BAGEL SHOP...
I WAS BAKING BAGELS, AND MITCH
WAS THE GENERAL MANAGER.
TILL THEY DITCHED THE BAGELS,
STARTED POURING THE CREPES...
CREPES UP.
AND FOLKS FLIPPED FOR 'EM.
IT'S FLUFFY AND LIGHT,
REALLY GOOD.
NUMBER ONE CRêPERIE.
JUST ASK CHEF TIM HEFTY.
CREPES ARE LOOKING GOOD.
WHEN I MOVED TO BOULDER, THIS
IS THE FIRST PLACE I HAD DINNER.
I LOVED THE PLACE.
I APPLIED FOR A JOB.
AND NOW HE'S CRANKING OUT
ALL KINDS OF CREPES.
(Tim) CHICKEN DUXELLES.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FAHGEDDABOUDIT.
FORGET ABOUT CREPE
IS NOT EASY TO FORGET.
FOOLISH CRAIG CREPE--I HAVE IT
FOR BREAKFAST ALL THE TIME.
AND FOR DESSERT...
BUTTER RUM CREPE--
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
STACKED 21 CREPES HIGH.
(French accent) NOW WE
ARE GOING TO MAKE ZE CREPE.
(French accent) ZE CREPES.
(normal voice) START OUT
WITH EGGS.
IT'S LIKE
A FAMILY REUNION IN THERE.
EXACTLY.
SOME MILK. BLEND THESE GUYS UP
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
MAKES YOU JUST WANT
TO DIVE RIGHT IN, DOESN'T IT?
AND I ADD IN THE SUGAR,
A LITTLE SALT,
AND THEN SOME
MELTED BUTTER.
IS IT le BEURRE
OR la BEURRE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK IT'S le BEURRE.
I ONLY TOOK TWO YEARS
OF FRENCH IN HIGH SCHOOL.
AND NOW THE FLOUR.
SO...
WHOA. WELCOME BACK TO
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OH, SO DIDN'T WANT
TO DO THAT.
OKAY, SO...
I HAVE TO INCORPORATE
THE FLOUR.
DO YOU WANT SOME HELP?
I DON'T KNOW. YOU DROPPED
THE WHISK LAST TIME.
YEAH. BUT TO REALLY MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S SUPER PURE.
YOU'RE GONNA GO
TO THE MIXER.
YEAH, JUST THROW THAT
IN THERE.
OH, IT'S CLEAN
THE WAY YOU WORK.
IT'S DEFINITELY
A MESSY PROCESS REGARDLESS.
LET ME JUST TURN THIS ON.
I'VE ALREADY LEARNED WHY
MY CREPES ARE NOT THAT GOOD.
(French accent) 'CAUSE
I DON'T PUT IN BLENDER.
YEAH, WE LIKE 'EM SMOOTH.
SO NOW WE'LL STRAIN IT.
(normal voice) WE'RE GOING
THROUGH CHUNK FILTRATION.
A LOT OF TIMES
THERE AREN'T THAT MANY CHUNKS.
BUT SEE, THERE'S STILL
THE STUFF POPPING UP.
WOW.
ALL RIGHT, SO YOU GET
THIS THING NICE AND HOT.
YOU ADD IN YOUR BATTER.
WHAT IS THIS?
THAT IS THE OFFICIAL
CREPE TWIRLER.
I AM SO OUT
OF MY ELEMENT.
GRAB YOUR CREPE
SWIRLING DEVICE,
SPIN THE BATTER AROUND,
JUST LIKE THAT.
AWESOME.
WORK THE CREPE.
FLIP THE CREPE.
OH, LET ME GET DOWN
WITH THIS.
RIGHT IN THE CENTER.
THERE WE GO. I THINK I WENT
A LITTLE TOO AGGRESSIVE
IN MY TWIRLING AND SPINNING.
(French accent) OH,
YOU CAN TRY CREPE CRACKER.
(normal voice) OKAY, THERE'S
ONE. NOT BAD, HUH, FOR A ROOKIE.
NOT BAD. LOOKS GOOD.
I'M BRINGING ONE
OF THESE HOME, LORI.
THREE CREPES DOWN.
UN, DEUX, TROIS.
AND THEN WE HIT IT WITH JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SAUCE.
SO YOU GOT YOUR BUTTER
AND SOME BROWN SUGAR,
A LITTLE CREAM,
A LITTLE BIT OF RUM.
WOW.
THREE MORE CREPES.
OKAY.
AND WE JUST KEEP
DOING THIS...
UNTIL WE'RE JUST COMPLETELY
OUT OF OUR MIND.
UNTIL WE'RE OUT OF THE CREPES,
AND OUR MINDS ARE MOSTLY GONE.
OKAY. LET IT COOL.
THEN WE FROST IT.
YES. ALL RIGHT,
CREAM CHEESE FROSTING--
A LITTLE CREAM CHEESE, A LITTLE
SOFTENED MELTED BUTTER...
(whistles)
A LITTLE BIT OF VANILLA.
GET THIS READY.
START IT A LITTLE LOW.
SO WE'RE CREAMING
THE BUTTER.
AND THE CREAM CHEESE,
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
AND THE POWDERED SUGAR'S
GOING IN.
YEAH, KIND OF SPEED IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S VERY DELICATE.
I LIKE TO DROP IT.
THEN I'LL SCRAPE DOWN
THE SIDES.
YOU JUST COAT THIS
LIKE YOU'RE DOING A CAKE.
JUST LIKE YOU'RE DOING
A CAKE.
FANTASTIC.
AND THAT'S ALL THERE IS TO IT.
WE JUST CHOP IT UP.
PLEASE TELL ME THAT'S NOT
THE SIZE YOU GIVE PEOPLE.
OH, YEAH.
WOW. MMM.
THE TEXTURE ON THAT
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE SWEETNESS
IS NOT OVER THE TOP.
USING THE CREAM CHEESE TO MAKE
THE FROSTING HELPS OUT A LOT.
MMM. I'VE NEVER
SEEN THIS BEFORE.
IT'S A GREAT RECIPE.
CALL THE PATENT OFFICE
RIGHT NOW, DUDE. THAT'S KILLER.
BUTTER RUM CREPE CAKE
UP IN THE WINDOW.
CREAMY, GREAT TEXTURE
TO IT.
(woman) YOUR BUTTER RUM
CARAMEL CREPE CAKE.
THE CHEWINESS OF THE CREPES
AND THE GOOEYNESS OF THE ICING.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
REUBEN UP.
(woman) EVERYTHING
IS HOMEMADE.
SANDWICHES--I LOVE
THEIR HOMEMADE BREAD.
I GOT SOME FRESH
BAGUETTES FOR YA.
YEP, THEY'VE GOT
THE CHOPS FOR THAT, TOO.
45 LOAVES A DAY OF BREAD
YOU GUYS MAKE HERE.
THREE DIFFERENT HOUSE BREADS--
THE WHEAT, RYE, AND BAGUETTE--
THEN THREE OR FOUR DIFFERENT
KINDS OF SPECIAL BREADS
THAT ROTATE IN AND OUT.
LIKE THIS CROWD FAVORITE.
(Tim) TOASTED OATMEAL
STOUT BREAD.
(woman) IT TASTES LIKE
IT JUST CAME OUT OF THE OVEN,
AND YOU CAN TELL
THE DIFFERENCE.
ROCK 'N' ROLL.
LET'S MAKE SOME BREAD.
WE ACTIVATE THE YEAST FIRST.
LET IT BLOOM.
YEAH. AND THEN WE JUST PUT
THE REDUCED STOUT BEER,
BUTTER, SALT, MOLASSES...
AND A LOT OF IT.
OATS, AND THEN
ALL SORTS OF FLOUR.
WHAT KIND OF FLOUR
WE GOT?
ALL-PURPOSE WHITE FLOUR.
THEN ADD IN OUR YEAST.
NOW WE JUST CRANK THIS THING UP
AND LET IT MIX.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 10 MINUTES,
15 MINUTES.
STARTS PULLING AWAY
FROM THE BOWL.
IT STARTS COMING OFF THE SIDES,
AND THEN IT'S READY TO GO.
WE PULL IT OUT,
STICK IT ON A SHEET TRAY,
OIL IT, COVER IT,
AND LET IT RISE OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE BRING IT OUT AGAIN
TO FLUFF UP FOR AN HOUR.
SMELL IT.
SMELLS AWESOME.
YEAH. WE WEIGH THIS OUT
TO 3-POUND, 1-OUNCE CHUNKS.
OKAY.
SO NOW YOU JUST GOT TO WORK
THE BREAD A LITTLE BIT,
STRETCH IT OUT, AND ROLL IT UP
INTO A BASIC LOAF SHAPE.
HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE AQUA NET.
PUT THEM
INTO THE BAKING PANS.
FILL IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
GIVE IT ONE SCORE,
SO IT--
YEAH, SO IT RISES UP
AND LOOKS LIKE A LOAF OF BREAD.
THEN I'LL BRUSH IT
WITH OIL.
PROOF AGAIN
IN THE BAKING PAN?
YEAH, OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE BRUSH 'EM WITH OATS
AND PUT THEM IN THE OVEN,
BAKE THEM FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR.
OATS, THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
le LOAF.
IT IS A FINISHED PRODUCT.
POP IT OUT OF THIS GUY.
STILL WEIGHS 3 POUNDS.
IT'S A PRETTY DENSE BREAD.
CUT IT UP.
MMM. SMELL THAT. MMM.
NOW WHAT'S THAT
GOING FOR?
THE B.L.T. GUACAMOLE.
LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT. GOT YOUR BREAD,
LIGHTLY TOASTED.
IS ALL THAT BACON
GOING ON THERE?
YES.
THAT IS A GOOD THING.
A LITTLE BIT OF MAYO.
GREAT BACON.
YEAH. TOMATOES,
THEN THE BACON.
LOOK AT THAT.
STACK DOWN THE BACON.
LOAD IT UP.
LETTUCE, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GUACAMOLE.
YOU MAKE THE GUACAMOLE.
YOU MAKE THE BREAD.
WOW. A LOT OF GUAC.
AND THEN BOOM, YOU'VE GOT
YOUR B.L.T. GUACAMOLE.
LOOK AT THAT
RATIO O' BACON.
MMM, MMM.
THE HOPPY-NESS I GET
OF THE BREAD,
IT'S KIND OF LIKE YOU ARE
DRINKING A BEER ALONGSIDE OF IT,
AND THEN THE GUACAMOLE--
SO NICE AND FRESH.
THE BACON IS CREAMY
AND SALTY.
THE BREAD'S FANTASTIC. DOES IT
JUSTICE, MAN. CONGRATS. MMM.
B.L.T. GUACAMOLE.
PACKED WITH FLAVOR--
IT'S HUGE.
YOU GET THE BACON
AND THE ONIONS, AVOCADO,
AND THAT BEAUTIFUL BREAD.
PESTO CHICKEN CREPE UP.
NUMBER ONE CRêPERIE,
FOR SURE.
REALLY?
IT'S ALL GOOD.
FOOLISH CRAIG...
YOU CAN ALWAYS FIND SOMETHING
THAT YOU WOULD LIKE.
YOU NAME IT, WE'VE GONE
ACROSS THE BOARD,
BUT WE'VE YET TO FIND ONE THAT
DID THE ROCKIN' CREPE.
HOMER READY TO GO. FRUIT CREPE
UP. CREPE CAKE READY.
THAT'S YOU GUYS.
NICE JOB.
THANKS SO MUCH.
UP NEXT...
HOMEMADE SOUP. YOU CAN
TASTE THE FRESHNESS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO QUEENS, NEW YORK...
THE FOOD'S TOP-NOTCH.
TO ROCK THE KREPLACH.
COMING BACK FOR THIS,
FOR SURE.
AS WE TRAVEL THE COUNTRY
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE FIND UNIQUE FOOD
IN UNIQUE PLACES,
BUT THERE'S REALLY SOMETHING
ABOUT HAVING
GREAT BARBECUE IN TEXAS
OR INCREDIBLE SEAFOOD
IN FLORIDA
OR MEXICAN FOOD
IN CALIFORNIA
OR GREAT JEWISH DELI FOOD
IN NEW YORK.
AND THAT BRINGS ME HERE,
TO REGO PARK, QUEENS,
IN NEW YORK CITY
TO CHECK OUT BEN'S BEST.
STUFFED CABBAGE UP.
EVERYONE LOVES IT.
MATZO BALL.
HOMEMADE SOUP.
YOU CAN TASTE THE FRESHNESS.
THERE YOU GO.
THE BRISKET
IS AMAZING, TOO.
WE HAVE A PICKUP.
THE FOOD'S TOP-NOTCH.
'CAUSE THIRD GENERATION
DELI MAN JAY PARKER...
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO,
GIRLS, PICK IT UP.
STILL FEELS THE PRESSURE.
I'M ONLY AS GOOD
AS MY LAST SANDWICH.
LET'S GO, I GOT
A TONGUE GOING OUT.
AND HE'S BEEN MAKING 'EM HERE
SINCE THE LATE '70s.
PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
THE DEAL WAS,
I WAS ON WALL STREET,
AND MY DAD ASKED ME
TO HELP SELL THIS PLACE.
I DECIDED THAT I LIKED IT, AND I
DECIDED TO BUY IT FROM HIM.
HOW LONG
HAS IT BEEN HERE?
65 YEARS.
HUNGARIAN GOULASH.
THE RECIPES ARE
EXACTLY THE SAME.
FRIED KREPLACH, PLEASE.
THIS IS OUTSTANDING.
IT'S LIKE A JEWISH
EGG ROLL.
CAN YOU SAY KREPLACH?
KREPLACH.
LACH?
YOU GOT IT.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD. THAT'S IT.
COME ON NOW.
BIG FLAP OF BRISKET.
WHERE WE GOING?
WE'RE GOING TO GRIND
INTO THE KREPLACH.
SALT, PEPPER,
GARLIC...
GRANULATED.
AND PAPRIKA.
SINCE WE'RE GONNA GRIND THIS,
WE'RE NOT TOO WORRIED
THAT IT'S EVENLY
DISPERSED.
NO, JUST WANT THE FLAVORS
TO BE IN THERE.
CELERY.
ONION.
A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
CARROTS. PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL, COVER IT.
AND HOW LONG'S THIS GONNA
GO DOWN FOR?
ABOUT THREE HOURS.
WE JUST WANT IT NICE
AND SOFT AND TENDER.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE BRISKET OUT
AND WE'RE GONNA CUT IT.
ALL RIGHT. NOW IT'S TIME
TO GRIND UP THE BRISKET.
RUN ALL THIS THROUGH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
THE VEGGIES.
ONIONS.
YOU GONNA THROW THE CARROT
IN THERE, BOSS?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
LET'S TRY A CARROT.
I NEVER DID ONE
BEFORE.
IN ALL THE YEARS THAT YOU'VE
BEEN LACHING THE KREP,
YOU'VE NEVER ADDED
A CARROT?
NO. LET ME JUST
THROW IN SOME SPICES--
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
SALT, PEPPER.
MIX THIS UP,
AND WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA BE MAKING
KREPLACH DOUGH.
FLOUR, WATER.
EGG SHADE--ALTHOUGH
IT LOOKS ORANGE,
IT COMES OUT
A LITTLE BIT YELLOW.
THROW IN AN EGG.
THROW IT RIGHT IN THERE.
SALT. THAT'S HOW
WE DO IT.
SO MIX THIS UP,
TAKE IT OUT...
LET IT SIT
FOR AN HOUR OR TWO.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO ROLL
THE KREPLACH DOUGH.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE PART.
IT'S REALLY GREAT FOR
UPPER BODY AND SHOULDERS.
WHAT ARE WE,
A PASTRY PILATE?
I LIKE THAT.
TRY TO MAKE KREPLACH DOUGH
AS THIN AS POSSIBLE.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA CUT IT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
DO IT BY HAND.
WELL, THEN LET ME GET IN
ON THIS.
SO IT'S LIKE I'M MAKING
LITTLE PIZZA.
YEAH.
THE KEY IS TO GET IT THIN
ENOUGH. THAT'S LOOKIN' GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
TAKE SOME MEAT.
THERE YOU ARE.
AND THEN WE FOLD IT IN HALF,
AND NOW WE PINCH THE SIDES DOWN.
WE GIVE IT SOME
EARS, OVER...
AND TIE IT THROUGH.
GOOD. NICE JOB.
EACH ONE IS DONE LIKE THIS?
WAY TO ROCK THE KREPLACH.
OKAY. PUTTING KREPLACH
IN THE FRYER, ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHTY THEN,
FRIED KREPLACH,
FRIED ONION.
NO DIPPING SAUCE?
I LIKE DUCK SAUCE
MYSELF.
DUCK SAUCE?
DUCK SAUCE.
IT'S A POT STICKER,
I KNEW IT WAS.
YOU FOUND US OUT.
LOOK HOW BIG
THIS IS.
MMM. COMING BACK
FOR THIS FOR SURE.
DUCK SAUCE,
OR THE SWEET-AND-SOUR SAUCE.
IT'S LIKE AN EGG ROLL.
MMM. IT'S GREAT WITH THIS.
THOSE ARE HEARTY.
GREAT CRUNCH, THE FILLING
IS NICE AND SUPER TENDER.
GOOD FRY, COMFORT FOOD.
AND KREPLACH.
I LIKE THE CRUNCHINESS,
AND THE BRISKET HAS
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
AND THEN THE ONIONS ON TOP
JUST TOTALLY MAKE IT.
MM-HMM. IT'S VERY YUMMY.
I GOTTA BE HONEST
WITH YOU,
WHEN I HEARD THAT WE WERE
MAKING KREPLACH,
I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA BE
IN A SOUP.
WELL, FUNNY YOU SHOULD
MENTION THAT.
WE BOIL IT AND PUT IT
IN THE SOUP.
OLD-FASHIONED
CHICKEN SOUP.
LOOK AT THAT.
KREPLACH.
AND WHAT'S IT CALLED,
CHICKEN IN THE POT?
CHICKEN IN--EVERY FRIDAY NIGHT
AS MY GRANDMOTHER MADE IT.
MMM, MMM.
THE CHICKEN IN THE POT--
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAVEN.
ENJOY.
OH, REALLY AUTHENTIC.
GOING OUT.
IT'S A THROWBACK
OF YEARS AGO...
YEAH.
WHEN YOU THOUGHT
OF A JEWISH DELI.
PICK UP ON
A PASTRAMI SANDWICH.
IN 1938, THERE WERE 2,000 KOSHER
DELIS IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK.
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
TODAY THERE ARE ONLY 16.
16 LEFT?
16 LEFT.
HERE WE GO.
BUT THIS IS ONE
OF THE ORIGINALS.
AND 65 YEARS LATER...
HOW'S EVERYTHING?
FOLKS ARE STILL PILING IN
FOR THE ORIGINAL MENU...
YOU HAVE CORNED BEEF.
YOU HAVE PASTRAMI.
YOUR NOODLE KUGEL,
YOUR BEEF TONGUE...
TONGUE, REALLY?
IT'S TERRIFIC.
AND THIS JEWISH DELI STAPLE.
STUFFED CABBAGE.
TASTES LIKE
IT'S HOMEMADE.
'CAUSE IT IS, THE WAY
JAY'S GRANDMA MADE IT.
IT'S PERFECT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
STUFFED CABBAGE.
WHAT DO WE STUFF
THE CABBAGE WITH?
WITH MEAT.
TAKE A PIECE OF CHUCK FLAT,
CUT IT INTO 2-INCH CUBES
IN ORDER TO GRIND IT
FOR THE STUFFED CABBAGE.
ALL RIGHT, SO THE MEAT'S GROUND
UP. NOW THE REST OF THE TOYS.
SUGAR.
COOKED RICE,
A LITTLE BINDER.
ONIONS.
A PRINCIPAL PAYMENT OF SOME
ONIONS. FINANCE DELI TALK.
AN ANNUITY OF BREAD CRUMB.
AN ANNUITY!
KETCHUP, GARLIC POWDER,
CUMIN, PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT ALL UP.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE
INTO, BROTHER?
WE'RE MAKING SWEET-AND-SOUR
RAISIN SAUCE.
STARTS WITH WATER...
VINEGAR.
WHITE VINEGAR...
SUGAR.
SUGAR, RAISINS...
RAISINS.
LEMON JUICE,
TOMATO PURéE...
TOMATO PASTE.
CRANBERRY SAUCE,
CINNAMON STICKS.
OKAY, SO LET THIS SIMMER...
ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE MAKE CABBAGE.
SO THESE ARE CORED, FROZEN,
AND RINSED IN HOT WATER.
AND THEY JUST GET SOFT.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE HAVE
THE CABBAGE LEAVES.
THEY'RE NICE AND SOFT.
FIRST WE COVER THE PAN.
WITH ALL THE PIECES
YOU'RE NOT GONNA USE.
DOESN'T BURN.
WE'RE GONNA LAY OUT
A FEW OF THE LEAVES.
AND YOU DOUBLE LEAF IT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE FILLING IN.
THAT'S A LOT OF MEAN,
MAN, FOR ONE.
YEAH. WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT,
PUSH THE SIDES IN.
THAT BIG?
YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
WANT TO GIVE
ONE OF THESE A TRY?
OH, LET ME
JUMP IN HERE.
I'M PUSHING IT IN OKAY?
NOT BAD FOR A FIRST SHOT.
NOT BAD FOR A ROOK?
YOU GOT IT.
SO YOU JUST KEEP LAYING
THESE OUT.
PUT SOME RAISIN SAUCE
OVER THE CABBAGE.
PUT LEAVES ON TOP, TOO,
SOME TINFOIL,
AND WE PUT IT IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHTY.
WE JUST BRING IT OUT.
HEAVY. WHOA.
THOSE LEAVES ARE NICE
AND TENDER.
HOW MANY COME
ON AN ORDER HERE?
TWO.
THERE'S OUR SWEET-AND-SOUR
RAISIN SAUCE.
SO TENDER.
UH, HOT.
MMM. DELICIOUS.
MMM, MMM.
THE CABBAGE IS SO TENDER.
YOU'D BE HARD-PRESSED TO TELL ME
IT'S NOT A NOODLE.
REALLY JUICY,
REALLY FLAVORFUL. MMM.
NICE KICK ON THE SOUR.
THIS IS REALLY DONE
WITH THE DISCIPLINE OF COOKING
IT CORRECTLY. ON POINT.
STUFFED CABBAGE.
IT'S A GREAT DISH.
JUICY, TENDER MEAT
INSIDE OF IT.
THE SAUCE
IS REALLY GOOD.
IT JUST MATCHES
REALLY WELL.
THERE YOU GO.
MUSHROOM BARLEY.
THIS IS WHERE PEOPLE WHO KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT
GO TO EAT.
BEST IN QUEENS.
HANDS DOWN?
NO QUESTION?
HANDS DOWN, NOT--
NOT EVEN A COMPARISON.
KREPLACH AND TONGUE,
PICK UP, PLEASE.
BEN'S BEST DELI
IS DEFINITELY A GEM.
HAND-MADE,
FAMILY RECIPE.
NICE JOB.
NEXT STOP...
ALL RIGHT,
FISH AND CHIPS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
RUBE WADDELL BURGER
COMIN' OVER.
TO TOP A BURGER
WITH WHAT ELSE?
CORNED BEEF ON TOP.
IT EATS LIKE A BURGER,
BUT IT TASTES LIKE
A CORNED BEEF SANDWICH.
I SO DIG THE VETERANS
OF THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
I MEAN, MOST OF 'EM HAVE DONE
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
I MEAN, THEY'RE WARRIORS.
THEY LOVE WHAT THEY DO.
SO I'M SO STOKED TO FIND A JOINT
HERE IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON,
WHERE THE OWNER
HAS DONE IT ALL.
HE'S BEEN AN ICE CARVER,
A KNIFE SHARPENER,
A PASTRY CHEF, A CATERING CHEF,
I MEAN, YOU NAME IT,
AND NOW HE'S GOT HIS OWN JOINT
WHERE HE'S SERVING UP COLD BEERS
AND BIG BURGERS.
THIS IS
WADDELL'S PUB & GRILLE.
ISLAND BURGER
WITH THE FRENCH FRIES.
THE BEST BURGERS
IN THE NORTHWEST AT LEAST.
I NEED A BIG DOG BURGER.
THEY'RE LIKE MY MOM'S,
FROM SCRATCH.
JAMIE, ORDER UP.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING,
AND THE SELECTION OF BEER
IS WONDERFUL.
THERE YOU GO, GUYS.
ALL THANKS TO OWNERS
MICHAEL NOBLE...
HOW MUCH TIME
ON THE GUINNESS MAC?
AND SKIP SELLS.
30 SECONDS.
SKIP AND I LOVE BEER.
GUINNESS MAC AND CHEESE.
WE LOVE GOOD FOOD.
MARRIED 'EM TOGETHER,
THIS IS WHAT
WE CAME UP WITH.
AND THEY NAMED THE JOINT AFTER
A HALL OF FAMER
WHO SHARED THEIR PASSION.
RUBE WADDELL.
FAMOUS BASEBALL PITCHER.
HE LOVED BASEBALL,
WORKING IN THE BARS,
GOOD FOOD.
THEY EVEN GAVE HIM
HIS OWN BURGER.
RUBE WADDELL BURGER.
IT'S LIKE THE BEST REUBEN
ON TOP OF MY HAMBURGER.
IT'S A MOUTHFUL OF FLAVOR.
MAKING CORNED BEEF FOR
OUR RUBE WADDELL BURGER.
ALL RIGHT.
BRISKET,
WHOLE CORIANDER.
THAT LITTLE TINKLE
SPRINKLE?
WE'LL ADD IT ALL FOR YOU.
DIG IT.
BAY LEAVES.
BOTH OF 'EM, HUH? OH--HE'S GOING
OFF--HE'S OFF THE RICHTER.
SOME RED PEPPER FLAKES.
OH, HE'S CRAZY TODAY.
CINNAMON STICKS.
LET'S GET 'EM ALL.
LOOK AT YOU
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
CRYSTALLIZED GINGER,
ORANGE ZEST.
PEEL OF THE ORANGE.
JUNIPERS.
JUNIPER BERRIES,
CLOVES.
NOW THIS IS OUR
HOUSE-MADE SEASON BLEND.
SQUIRRELLY BEAVER.
SQUIRRELLY BEAVER
SEASON ALL.
BROKEN DOWN AS SUGAR,
CRACKED PEPPER, SALT,
SMOKED PAPRIKA...
AND?
AND CUMIN.
ADD THE WATER TO COVER.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS BRINE?
THIS BRINES FOR 24 HOURS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ROAST
IT OFF IN THAT LIQUID?
YES. 350-DEGREE OVEN
FOR 3 HOURS.
COVERED.
ALL RIGHT, WE COOLED IT
AND TRIMMED IT.
NOW IT'S GONNA GO
ON THE GRILL?
IT'S GONNA GO ON
THE CHAR BROILER.
ANOTHER EXTRA LAYER
OF FLAVOR.
AND ONCE WE GET AT THIS,
WE PUT A LITTLE CHAR.
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
SLICE IT THIN?
SLICE THIS LIKE SO.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE READY FOR OUR
RUBE WADDELL BURGER.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
THE REUBEN DRESSING.
START WITH THE MAYONNAISE.
EXTRA HEALTHY PORTION.
KETCHUP,
SWEET PICKLE CHIPS.
SO WE'VE GOT A THOUSAND ISLAND
HERE RIGHT NOW.
SWEET PICKLE JUICE.
NOW WITH THE 97 OTHER THOUSAND
THINGS GOING INTO IT.
ONION POWDER,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
SUGAR, CHOPPED ONIONS,
SOME RED BELL PEPPERS.
NICE.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR--
GIVE A LITTLE TANG TO IT--
RED PEPPER FLAKES,
SMOKED PAPRIKA.
COME ON,
GET IT IN THERE.
OH, YEAH,
THERE WE GO.
GO BIG.
SALT, SOME OF OUR
SQUIRRELLY BEAVER SEASON ALL.
NOW WORCESTERSHIRE
SAUCE.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
SO ALL THAT MIXED TOGETHER,
LET IT CHILL DOWN,
AND THIS IS GONNA GO
ON WHAT?
GONNA GO ON
THE RUBE WADDELL BURGER.
NOW WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR RANCHER PATTIES.
FRESH CERTIFIED
ANGUS BEEF.
WE ADD A LITTLE DOUBLE SMOKED
BACON TO IT, JUST TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE MORE EXTRA--
WHY WOULDN'T YOU?
YEAH. THIS IS OUR SQUIRRELLY
BEAVER RANCHER'S SEASONING,
BROKEN DOWN AS SALT,
CUMIN...
AND THE TURMERIC
FOR THE COLOR?
YEAH. SOME ROSEMARY,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
RED PEPPER FLAKES, THEN WE MIX
IT ALL, INCORPORATE IT IN,
GO AHEAD AND MAKE
OUR PATTIES RIGHT AWAY.
OKAY, SO YOU JUST
HAND-FORM ALL THESE?
HAND-FORM 'EM ALL.
THERE THEY ARE.
PATTY. OKAY.
GONNA LET THAT
COOK DOWN.
TOAST A BUN, ONIONS, PUT
A LITTLE BACON GREASE IN THERE.
LOVE THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE IT
IN A SQUIRT BOTTLE.
SAUERKRAUT,
CORNED BEEF ON TOP.
NOW JUST FLIP IT.
CORNED BEEF--
CORNED BEEF'S DONE.
SWISS CHEESE, PUT IT
ON A RANCHER PATTY,
PUT OUR DRESSING ON.
THE 9,000-INGREDIENT
REUBEN DRESSING.
BURGER GOES ON.
I'M NOT TYPICALLY A GUY
THAT CUTS A BURGER IN HALF,
BUT JUST SO I CAN
SHOW YOU THE MONSTROSITY.
READY? HERE WE GO.
IT EATS LIKE A BURGER,
BUT IT TASTES LIKE
A CORNED BEEF SANDWICH.
SEE, I LOVE PASTRAMI ON IT,
LOT OF KRAUT,
GOOD QUALITY BREAD,
GOOD SAUCE,
BUT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THE KEY TO THAT BAD BOY
IS THAT SEASONED CORNED BEEF
THAT HE MADE HIMSELF--
CORIANDER--THE BURGER'S
A MONSTER, BRO.
ALL RIGHT,
I GOT A RUBE WADDELL.
THE CRUNCHINESS
OF THE ONIONS.
THE SAUERKRAUT'S
FRESH AND AMAZING.
SO MUCH SAUCE AND GOODNESS
COMING OUT OF THIS.
THE RUBE WADDELL
BURGER COMIN' OVER.
WHAT MAKES
A GOOD BURGER?
GOTTA HAVE CREATIVITY.
SWEET AND TANGY BURGER--
THAT'S A TASTY BURGER.
THERE IT IS BURGER--
WE JUST KEEP ON COMIN' UP
WITH MORE AND MORE.
LIKE THIS MONSTER...
BIG DOG BURGER
WITH SWEET FRIES...
AMAZING. JALAPEÑO,
BACON, BURGER,
ONION RING--ALL IN ONE.
ALL RIGHT,
BURGER TIME.
BIG DOG TIME.
SO THE RANCHER PATTY
HAS GOT THE PORK IN IT
AND ALL THE SEASONING,
AND THEN AN 80/20.
EXACTLY. GOOD FLAVORS
FROM BOTH BURGERS.
TOASTED BUN.
PEPPER JACK AND CHEDDAR.
PUT SOME HAM IN BETWEEN
THE BURGERS.
NOW OVER HERE,
OUR HOUSE-MADE ZACH SAUCE.
BARBECUE MAYO.
ONION RINGS.
OH, COME ON NOW.
YOU GOTTA HAVE IT.
SOME JALAPEÑOS. STACK IT.
BACON ON TOP. LID IT, STAB IT.
THAT'S THE BIG DOG BURGER.
SHOULD CALL THAT
THE RIDICULOUS BURGER.
AND GO.
WHAT, DID YOUR SISTER
TAKE A BITE OF THAT?
THERE YOU GO. LOVE THE CRUNCH,
LOVE THE COMPLEXITY OF FLAVORS.
LOT OF MEAT. LIKE THAT
LITTLE JALAPEÑO AT THE END.
BRING A FRIEND
AND PACK AN APPETITE,
IT'LL TAKE TWO OF YOU
TO GET AFTER THE BIG DOG.
ALL RIGHT,
I HAVE A BIG DOG.
THE CHEESE IN THE CENTER AND AN
ONION RING ON THE BOTTOM--
IT'S GREAT.
BIG DOG BURGER
WITH SWEET FRIES.
THE EAGER BEAVER
SEASONING,
AND THE SIZE OF THE BURGER
IS GIGANTIC.
IT'S GREAT FOOD,
AND A GREAT
BEER SELECTION.
AND YOUR I.P.A.
THE MOST BEER ON TAP
IN SPOKANE.
THE MOST?
THE MOST.
35 HANDLES.
THERE'S A LOT OF BEER-FLAVORED
FOODS ON THE MENU.
LIKE MAC AND CHEESE
COOKED IN GUINNESS...
GUINNESS MAC
IN THE WINDOW.
FISH TACOS DIPPED
IN CORONA BATTER,
AND A LAMB CHEESESTEAK
BRAISED IN STOUT.
LAMB DIP FOR YOU.
WE'RE COOKING IT, BRAISING IT,
AND MAKING IT HERE AT WADDELL'S.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
THAT'S ABSOLUTELY
AMAZING.
AT WADDELL'S PUB & GRILLE
IN SPOKANE, WASHINGTON...
ALL RIGHT,
THE FISH AND CHIPS.
OWNERS SKIP SELLS
AND MICHAEL NOBLE...
ALL RIGHT, I'M MELTIN'
CHEESE ON THE LAMP DIP.
ARE SERVING UP
A ONE-OF-A-KIND CHEESESTEAK.
LAMB CHEESESTEAK.
LAMB-TASTIC, I HEAR.
IT IS.
OKAY, WHAT UP NEXT?
LEG OF LAMB. TAKE OUR
STRAINED BACON GREASE.
OH, OH!
LOVE THAT SMOKY GOOD FLAVOR.
SQUIRRELLY BEAVER SEASON ALL.
RUB IT DOWN REALLY GOOD,
AND THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
SO WE SEASONED THE LEG,
WE GOT THE FAT.
WE'RE READY TO SEAR.
ADD SOME BACON GREASE.
SEARING ON BOTH SIDES.
SEAR ON BOTH SIDES,
LOCKS IN THAT MOISTURE,
TRAPS IN THAT GOOD FLAVOR
OF THE LAMB.
PULL THAT OFF,
NOW WE ADD IN OUR MIREPOIX.
CARROTS, ONIONS, CELERY,
AND WE ADD GARLIC.
NOW WE STIR THAT AROUND.
JUST LOOKING FOR THAT
DEEP, RICH FLAVOR.
NATURAL SUGARS
WILL HELP.
ADD SOME TOMATO PASTE,
COOK THAT DOWN.
CARAMELIZE ALL THE SUGARS.
ADD OUR LAMB BACK IN.
OKAY.
ADD OUR DARK STOUT BEER.
ABOUT THREE-QUARTERS
OF THE WAY UP.
THIS GIVES A GOOD RICH BODY
TO THE AU JUS.
FINISH WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER.
SO IT'S COVERING
BY ABOUT AN INCH.
THEN WE ADD OUR
WHOLE PEPPERCORNS,
SOME RED PEPPER FLAKES.
WE HAVE BAY LEAF.
WE COVER AND BRAISE FOR ABOUT
3 HOURS AT 350 DEGREES.
NOW AFTER IT'S
BEEN BRAISED...
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE. MEAT SHOULD FALL
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
SO WE CAN ROAST IT.
SO WE SHRED THE MEAT.
WE'LL LEAVE THAT
TO CHILL UP.
WE'RE CARAMELIZING
THE LEG BONE.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
OVER THERE.
TAKE THE BONE, ROAST IT OFF,
AND NOW IT'S GONNA GO BACK IN,
REALLY KINDA BRING IN TOGETHER
THIS AU JUS FOR THE LAMB.
YEAH.
AND HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THAT GONNA GO?
20 MINUTES.
LET IT REDUCE DOWN
EVEN MORE.
LET IT REDUCE DOWN.
AND THEN YOU JUST
STRAIN IT?
YES. NOW WE ADD
THE AU JUS MIX.
FORTIFIED WITH
A LITTLE BEEF PASTE.
NOW STIR,
BRING TO A BOIL.
COOL IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
THEN WE'LL MARRY THAT
WITH THE SHREDDED LAMB?
YES.
THIS JUST GETS A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF THAT GOOD BRAISING LIQUIDS
INTO THE MEAT.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF THAT,
SO IT DOESN'T DRY OUT
WHEN IT GOES ON THE FLATTOP.
EXACTLY.
OKAY, LET'S BUILD THIS. WE WANT
A LITTLE CRISPY IN THERE,
BUT NOT TOO MUCH.
LET THAT COOK A LITTLE BIT.
TOAST A BUN. CHEDDAR CHEESE
GOES REALLY GOOD WITH THIS LAMB.
ALL RIGHT.
PUT A LITTLE WADDELL MAYO
ON THERE.
MAYO WITH TERIYAKI SAUCE.
AND THIS GOES ON TOP.
NICE AND JUICY.
OUR LAMB AU JUS.
I ALWAYS THINK SANDWICHES
LIKE THIS NEED A DIP.
NOW WHAT DO WE CALL
THIS LAMB-STROSITY?
THIS IS THE IRISH
LAMB DIP.
DELICIOUS.
RIGHT ON POINT.
THOSE THAT REALLY LIKE LAMB
WILL REALLY ENJOY THIS.
ANYBODY THAT DOESN'T
THINK THEY LIKE LAMB,
I CHALLENGE 'EM TO TRY THIS
AND TELL ME THEY DON'T DIG IT.
THAT TERIYAKI MAYO ADDS
JUST A LITTLE HINT OF SWEET.
I COULD CHUG THE AU JUS.
YOU PICK THE BEER UP FOR SURE.
YOU KNOW, YOU GET THAT
TRUE LAMB FLAVOR.
THIS IS THE WAY YOU SHOULD
DO IT. RIGHT ON POINT, MAN.
I HAVE A LAMB DIP
FOR YOU.
THE FIRST THING YOU GET
IS THE LAMB RIGHT AWAY.
THE MEAT IS
AMAZINGLY JUICY.
THE AU JUS--YOU CAN ACTUALLY
TASTE THE GUINNESS.
IRISH LAMB DIP!
BUT ANYTIME
YOU GET DIP--
WELL, YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
THAT JUST SAYS...
THE SLEDDER HOUSE.
THE FOOD IS PHENOMENAL.
RUBE WADDELL BURGER
WITH THE FRENCH FRIES.
GREAT FOOD, GREAT PEOPLE,
GREAT PLACE.
SERVE A QUALITY PRODUCT,
GIVING A GOOD PRICE,
AND BEING HERE ALL THE TIME
WORKING YOUR BUTT OFF,
AND I GOTTA TELL YOU SOMETHING,
MAN, YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
YOU GUYS, GET DOWN HERE BEFORE
THIS PLACE GETS PACKED.
THERE'S ALREADY A LINE
OUT THE DOOR.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WE HAVE HERE...
A POT FROM THE CHINESE
RESTAURANT.
I'VE HAD DIM SUM
OUT OF THIS THING.
HAVEN'T WE BEEN THROUGH
THIS ALREADY?
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH THIS
ALREADY,
YOU DIM SUM POT
RIPPER-OFFER!