HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(woman) WE GOT IT.
FUNKY FINDS...
SHE'S THE INTERNATIONAL
CHICKEN-STACKING CHAMPION.
IN STONE HARBOR,
NEW JERSEY.
TWO CRAB CAKES.
THE SEAFOOD SHACK...
IT'S GOT, LIKE,
A SHACK FEEL,
BUT IT'S HIGH-END,
CREATIVE FOOD.
WHERE SERVING IT FRESH...
MY MOUTH IS WATERING.
MEANS A TASTE
OF SOUTH AMERICA.
(woman)
I HAVE THE MOQUECA.
THAT'S RIGHT DOWN TO IT,
FANTASTIC.
IN LONG ISLAND CITY,
NEW YORK...
(woman)
SWEET POTATO BRûLéE.
THE TINY JOINT...
EVERYTHING'S FRESH HERE.
THAT'S WHAT I LOVE.
GOING BIG...
(whistling)
WITH FRESH ROASTED CHICKEN.
LIKE FRED FLINTSTONE
CORN ON THE COB.
AND THEY'RE
TAKING BACON...
THEY LIKE
THEIR BACON STUFF.
TO THE MAX.
(woman)
BACON BROWNIE.
REALLY?
AND IN SANTA ROSA,
CALIFORNIA...
POLENTA AND CHICKEN SAUSAGE.
THE JOINT IN MY BACKYARD...
YOU LOOKING FOR SOMETHING
THAT'S REALLY GOOD? THIS IS IT.
TURNING OUT...
(man) HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
A WHOLE NEW GENERATION
OF CHEFS.
WHICH ONE
DO YOU LIKE?
I KINDA LIKE
THAT ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
ABOUT 40 MINUTES SOUTH
OF ATLANTIC CITY
AND SAY AN HOUR AND 15 MINUTES
EAST OF PHILADELPHIA
IS A LITTLE SHORE TOWN
KNOWN AS STONE HARBOR.
NOW IT'S HOME
TO A SEASONAL RESTAURANT
THAT'S ONLY OPEN FIVE MONTHS
OUT OF THE YEAR.
BUT THEY ARE KNOCKING OUT
FRESH SEAFOOD
WITH A SOUTH AMERICAN TWIST.
THIS IS QUAHOG'S SEAFOOD SHACK.
(man) MOQUECA.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA GET
A REALLY EXTRAORDINARY MEAL.
FROM SHRIMP EMPANADA...
(man) THAT'S READY.
TO A SOUTH AMERICAN CEVICHE.
TUNA AND WATERMELON.
MM-HMM, VERY GOOD.
EVEN LOBSTER TAQUITOS.
(woman)
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
CHEF CARLOS DOES A GREAT JOB
EXECUTING THE MEAL.
THAT'D BE ARGENTINEAN-BORN
CARLOS BARROZ...
TWO TORTELLONI.
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT
THREE YEARS AGO
TO GIVE THE LOCALS
WHAT THEY LOVE...
TWO CRAB CAKES.
AND TO TURN THEM ON
TO WHAT HE LOVES.
PACU RIBS ARE TO DIE FOR.
IT'S SO UNIQUE.
YOU'LL NEVER FIND 'EM
ANYWHERE.
'CAUSE THESE
BARBECUE RIBS...
TWO PACU RIBS.
ARE FROM A FISH.
WHAT KIND OF FISH
IS THIS?
A PACU.
THIS IS
THE PACU FISH.
THAT IS
A PACU FISH.
AND WHERE'S THAT FROM?
BRAZIL.
BRAZILIAN DISH.
THAT'S A--YEAH.
LET ME SHOW YOU.
PORTIONS LOOK LIKE
BABY BACK RIBS, YEAH?
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE DOES THIS
COME FROM?
THE AMAZON RIVER.
FROM THE AMAZON RIVER.
YEAH. THAT'S
A VEGETARIAN FISH.
YEAH. THEY EAT
VEGETABLES AND FRUIT.
REALLY?
YEAH, REALLY.
ALL RIGHT, RIBS ARE CUT.
NOW WE MAKE THE SAUCE?
RIGHT.
AND IT'S A...
ORANGE-CHIPOTLE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WHAT DO WE
START WITH?
SO WE START
WITH THE BUTTER, GARLIC,
SPANISH ONION. WE SAUTé
TILL THE ONIONS GET CLEAR.
A LITTLE TRANSLUCENT.
YEAH. WE ADD
THE KETCHUP,
CHIPOTLE PASTE,
SOY SAUCE.
WOW,
THIS IS, LIKE, THE INTERNATIONAL
BARBECUE SAUCE.
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
GOES INTERNATIONAL.
OKAY, A LITTLE
BROWN SUGAR.
HONEY.
SO YOU GOT THE SWEET
AND THE HEAT.
THE ORANGES,
A LITTLE BIT
OF LIME JUICE.
LET IT REDUCE.
30 TO 40 MINUTES.
NOW THE BARBECUE SAUCE
IS GOING TO THE BLENDER.
NOW ORANGE ZEST.
SO YOU GET THE REALLY NICE
OILS OF THE ORANGE,
BUT NOT THE CITRUS FACTOR.
NOT THE CITRUS. YEAH.
AND THEN WE BLEND IT TO BREAK UP
THE CHUNKS OF THE GARLIC
AND THE ONIONS.
LOOK AT THAT. (whistles)
NOW WE PUT THE SAUCE
ON THE FISH.
HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THESE MARINATE?
TWO HOURS.
WHAT DO WE DO
FOR TWO AND A HALF HOURS
WHILE WE WAIT?
UH, LET'S GO TO THE BAR AROUND
THE CORNER AND HAVE A BEER,
AND THEN WE'LL
COME BACK.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE ARE READY
TO GRILL IT.
SO WE GRILL 'EM
FIVE MINUTES EACH SIDE?
YEAH. BRUSH 'EM
ONE MORE TIME.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU HAVE,
LIKE, TEN ORDERS COOKING THERE,
CARLITO?
I NEED GLASSES.
YES, YOU DO.
YEAH. CAN I BORROW
YOUR GLASSES?
THANK YOU.
NOW THERE YOU GO.
WE BRUSH THE DISH.
NOW THE RIBS GO ONTO THE PLATE.
ORANGE SEGMENT ON THE TOP
OF THE RIBS,
A LITTLE MORE SCALLION, FRESH
ORANGE ZEST ALL OVER THE DISH
AND LEMON ZEST,
CHIVE OIL.
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
WHEN I DROVE UP
TO A SEAFOOD JOINT
ON THE WATER IN NEW JERSEY,
I WASN'T EXPECTING
I WAS GONNA GET THAT KIND
OF PLATE PRESENTATION.
I DIDN'T EXPECT I WAS GONNA
BE EATING FISH RIBS.
OH. THAT'S CRAZY.
YOU SEE THE BONES?
A FISH THAT'S RELATED
TO DINOSAURS,
BUT IT TASTES FANTASTIC.
THAT'S SOMETHING I WOULD
ORDER AGAIN FOR SURE.
THE PRESENTATION ON IT,
IN MY OPINION,
WAS OF ANY FIVE-STAR
RESTAURANT.
THAT'S UP THERE IN SOME OF
THE BEST FISH I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
SERIOUSLY IMPRESSED.
THANK YOU.
DYNAMITE.
FALLS RIGHT OFF THE BONE,
REALLY TASTY.
THE MEAT'S EXCELLENT.
IT'S JUST PERFECT.
GOOD BARBECUE SAUCE,
NOT TOO SPICY.
YEP.
WHO KNEW FISH
HAD RIBS, RIGHT?
AT A JOINT
THAT LOOKS LIKE
JUST ANOTHER SEAFOOD SHACK.
IT'S GOT, LIKE,
A SHACK FEEL,
BUT IT'S HIGH-END,
CREATIVE FOOD.
WERE YOU SURPRISED TO FIND
THIS VARIATION OF SEAFOOD?
WE WERE PLEASANTLY
SURPRISED.
I'M DRIVING THROUGH HERE.
I'M THINKING,
FISH AND CHIP JOINT,
OLD-SCHOOL SEAFOOD HOUSE.
BUT HE IS DOING
THOSE FAVORITES, TOO.
(Carlos)
ONE SOFT-SHELLED CRAB.
YOU DO FRIED CLAMS.
YOU DO FRIED SHRIMP.
YEAH, WE DO ALL THE TRADITIONAL
NEW ENGLAND STYLE.
EVEN A CLASSIC
LOBSTER BAKE.
OUT OF SIGHT.
ANYTHING WITH A SHELL
IS IN THIS BOWL.
BUT WHAT STILL
MAKES HIM THE PROUDEST...
THERE YOU GO.
IS TURNING
JERSEY SHORE FOLKS...
MMM.
ONTO THE STUFF HE GREW UP WITH
IN SOUTH AMERICA.
TWO MOQUECAS. THAT'S A BRAZILIAN
FISHERMAN'S STEW,
BUT WITH COCONUT MILK.
SO IN BRAZILIAN FOOD--
A LOT OF COCONUT?
A LOT OF COCONUT.
START WITH BUTTER,
A LITTLE BIT OF BLENDED OIL.
COOK WITH THE OIL, BUT YOU GET
THE FLAVOR WITH THE BUTTER.
GARLIC, RED ONIONS,
GREEN PEPPERS, RED PEPPERS,
SOME CLAMS, MUSSELS.
THIS IS
GONNA BE GOOD.
WHITE WINE
AND NOW CLAM JUICE
WITH ANOTHER POT ON THE TOP
TILL THE CLAMS OPEN.
IF THEY DON'T OPEN,
DON'T EAT 'EM.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
START MAKING THE RICE
FOR THE FISHERMAN'S STEW--
COCONUT MILK, RICE, CHIVE OIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
SO NOW THE CLAMS--
THEY ARE OPEN.
SO THAT MEANS IT'S READY
FOR THE REST OF THE SEAFOOD.
MAKO SHARK.
YOU'RE GONNA MAKO
THAT SHARK TASTE GOOD.
YES. SOME CHORIZO.
AND THE CHORIZO
IS BIG IN BRAZILIAN
AND ARGENTINEAN
COOKING?
IN ARGENTINEAN
COOKING, YES.
SCALLOPS, SHRIMPS.
THAT'S A LOT
OF SEAFOOD, MAN.
YEAH, CALAMARIS.
COOK THIS JUST TILL
IT'S PERFECTLY DONE,
AND THEN SERVE IT UP?
YEAH. COCONUT MILK,
A LITTLE MORE CLAM JUICE--
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
ANNATTO OIL.
YOU KNOW ANNATTO?
I KNOW
THE ANNATTO SEED.
ALMOST READY--WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE LAST FOUR THINGS.
EDAMAMES.
EDAMAMES?
EDAMAMES, YEAH--
THE SOYBEANS.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
ABOUT EDAMAMES?
I TRAVELED AROUND THE WORLD--
WHEN I WAS IN JAPAN.
SRIRACHA.
OH, THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
LIME AND LEMON JUICE,
FRESH SQUEEZED.
CILANTRO,
AND THAT'S IT.
LOOKS GREAT, MAN.
LET ME TASTE THIS.
MY MOUTH IS WATERING.
THAT'S NICE,
REALLY NICE.
WE ARE READY.
LOOK AT THIS. SMELL IT.
OH, DON'T TEASE ME.
NOW WE MAKE A LITTLE HOLE
IN THE MIDDLE FOR THE RICE.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
THAT'S OUTTA CONTROL.
SCALLOPS, CLAMS,
MUSSELS--
THE ONLY PROBLEM
IS YOU CAN ONLY GET THIS
FIVE MONTHS
OUT OF THE YEAR.
CHORIZO...
(speaking indistinctly)
WOW, THAT'S UP THERE
WITH MY TOPS, MAN.
THAT'S--THAT IS SOME
OF THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
THAT'S RIGHT DOWN TO IT,
FANTASTIC.
I WANT SOME, OKAY?
DON'T FINISH THAT ONE.
(speaking
indistinctly)
OKAY.
I WOULDN'T CHANGE
A THING ON THIS,
EXCEPT GETTING IT
ALL YEAR-ROUND.
I HAVE THE MOQUECA.
GOOD BLEND OF, LIKE,
SPICE AND FISH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF
MO' MOQUECA.
YOU BETTER OPEN 12 MONTHS
A YEAR, BUDDY.
WE'LL DRIVE ALMOST FOUR HOURS
JUST TO HAVE DINNER.
IT'S FABULOUS.
LIKE, IT'S A SHACK,
SO I LOVE IT.
FOOD'S GREAT, EXCELLENT.
THAT'S WHY WE COME BACK.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
CARLITO. OH, SOMEONE'S HERE
WITH A DELIVERY.
(laughs)
UP NEXT...
THIS IS MY BEST MEAL
OF THE DAY.
WE'RE HEADING
TO LONG ISLAND CITY...
ENJOY THAT.
THANK YOU.
TO A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S GOING BIG
ON THE BACON.
WE'RE NOT FAKIN',
WE'RE ROLLIN' WITH THE BACON.
I'M RIGHT ACROSS THE EAST RIVER
FROM MIDTOWN MANHATTAN,
IN LONG ISLAND CITY, QUEENS,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT--
GET THIS--
ONCE HAD THREE SEATS.
WELL, NOW THEY'VE GONE
FULL-BLOWN,
AND THEY'RE OFFERING UP
LOCALLY GROWN COMFORT FOOD
TO--YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT--
14 SEATS.
I KNOW. IT'S GO BIG
OR GO HOME.
THIS IS SAGE GENERAL STORE.
HERE'S YOUR ROTISSERIE CHICKEN
AND YOUR BEETS.
IT'S A PRETTY SMALL PLACE,
COZY AND HOMEY.
THAT'S WHAT THIS KIND
OF FOOD IS.
(man)
BACON GRILLED CHEESE.
GOOD HOMEY FOOD.
TURKEY MEAT LOAF--
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
WE MAKE EVERYTHING
FROM SCRATCH.
'CAUSE OWNER
LESLIE NILSSON...
THERE YOU GO.
WON'T HAVE IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
SAME MISSION STATEMENT,
I'M PROUD TO SAY, FOR 14 YEARS.
I THOUGHT IT WAS,
"WE'RE NOT FAKIN',
WE'RE ROLLIN' WITH THE BACON."
AND THAT'S REALLY
THE OTHER ONE.
THAT'S THE OTHER
ONE--TWO.
THEY LIKE THEIR BACON STUFF.
THEY PUT IT ON THEIR PIZZAS.
BACON PIZZA.
(woman)
BACON BROWNIE.
REALLY? ROCK STAR?
ROCK STAR.
(Leslie)
SIDE OF BACON MAC.
THE RICHNESS
OF THE BACON,
ALONG WITH SORT OF
THE ARTISANAL CHEESES.
ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS.
IT SHOULD BE CHEESE
AND MAC.
IT SHOULD BE.
WE'VE GOT SWISS,
FONTINA...
MMM.
AGED CHEDDAR
FROM VERMONT,
LOCAL GOAT CHEESE,
AND SOME BLUE CHEESE,
AND A LITTLE
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
AND THEN OUR
NUESKE'S BACON.
WOW. OKAY, WELL,
LET'S GET THIS GOING.
WE ADD THE WATER AND SOME SALT.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL THAT MACARONI.
SO...
NOW SHE'S GONNA NEED
TO HURRY UP AND MAKE THIS,
OR I WILL EAT
ALL OF THE BACON.
ORGANIC MILK,
A LITTLE BIT
OF EVAPORATED MILK...
YES.
AND THAT JUST MAKES IT
ALL SMOOTHER.
BUT NOT SWEETENED
CONDENSED.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
OKAY.
NOW THE CHEESINESS
BEGINS--
SOME SWISS...
ADDS A NICE,
LITTLE TANG TO THAT.
FONTINA MAKES IT
NICE AND MELTY. OKAY.
(speaking
indistinctly)
AGED VERMONT CHEDDAR,
LOCAL GOAT CHEESE,
AND BLUE CHEESE
FOR EDGINESS.
SO IT'S LOW AND SLOW
AND LOTS OF STIRRING
TILL THIS REALLY MELTS UP
NICE. NOW WHAT?
A LITTLE
DRIED MUSTARD
THAT'S BEEN MIXED
WITH SOME WATER.
HYDRATED--
I DIG IT.
SALT, PEPPER, HOT SAUCE,
HEAVY CREAM.
LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
OUR NUESKE'S BACON.
THANK YOU.
GOURMET BACON--
WHAT I ALWAYS RECOMMEND
IS THAT IF YOU NEED A POUND
OF BACON TO COOK WITH,
MAKE 2.
(laughing)
SO LET THE CHEESE SAUCE
COOK DOWN JUST A BIT.
STRAIN THE MAC AND...
MAKE THE BREADCRUMBS--
FRESHLY GROUND BREADCRUMBS,
MELTED BUTTER,
PARSLEY.
CAYENNE.
SALT AND PEPPER. FLASH IT
IN THE OVEN 10 TO 15 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER.
MACARONI.
STIR THAT UP.
MMM.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUT
THE BREADCRUMBS.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER FOR YOU.
GREAT.
MMM. FANTASTIC
MAC AND CHEESE.
PREMIUM BACON, GREAT CHEESES--
THE GOAT AND THE BLUE--
YOU GET A LITTLE TANG
BACK THERE.
THIS IS GOURMET,
GRADE "A" MAC AND CHEESE,
MACK DADDY
MAC AND CHEESE.
ABSOLUTELY
OUTSTANDING.
(Leslie) AND AN ORDER
OF BACON MAC AND CHEESE.
YOU GET THE SMOKY FLAVOR
FROM THE BACON.
IT'S DECADENT. AND YOU KNOW
THAT YOU'RE GONNA
GET GOOD FOOD
WHEN YOU COME HERE.
WHICH IS WHY FOLKS
ARE LINING UP...
CAN I GET SHORT RIBS
WITH A SIDE OF
SWEET POTATO BRûLéE?
FOR COMFORT FOOD...
ENJOY THAT.
THANK YOU.
DONE LESLIE'S WAY.
ENJOY.
BEETS AND COLLARD GREEN--
COLLARD GREENS
IN LONG ISLAND CITY?
IT'S A LITTLE RISKY,
I KNOW.
IT'S REALLY GOOD FOOD.
THE SWEET POTATO BRûLéE--
DELICIOUS.
HERE WE GO.
THIS IS THE FUN PART.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. PUMPKIN PIE-ESQUE.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH HERE.
THAT'S WHAT I LOVE.
YOU BAKE
YOUR OWN GOODS.
MACAROONS--
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
SALMON PIZZA'S UP.
IT'S A GREAT
WOOD-OVEN PIZZA.
IT IS THE BEST PIZZA OVEN
IN THE WORLD.
ABSOLUTELY.
THIS THING GETS, LIKE,
750 DEGREES ON THE DECK,
1,000 IN THE DOME.
I LIKE GOOD EQUIPMENT,
YOU KNOW?
YOU THINK?
THIS IS MY ROTISSERIE
THAT WE IMPORTED FROM FRANCE.
YOU KNOW, IN PARIS THEY HAVE 'EM
SIT OUTSIDE THE RESTAURANTS,
AND YOU SMELL IT, AND YOU
JUST WANT TO BUY A CHICKEN.
I WANTED THAT
PARTICULAR ROTISSERIE.
ROTISSERIE CHICKEN.
THIS IS THE CHICKEN I WISH
I COULD MAKE AT HOME.
IT'S VERY FLAVORFUL.
NOW LET'S TALK
ABOUT BRINING THE BIRD.
THIS, TO ME, IS AN ULTIMATE
MUST-DO WITH POULTRY.
FIRST WE'LL ADD THE WATER,
SUGAR, SOME SALT.
STIR IT UP REAL GOOD.
OUR BEAUTIFUL
ORGANIC CHICKENS.
HOW LONG YOU GONNA
BRINE THESE BIRDS?
USUALLY OVERNIGHT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
ON TO?
AN AMAZING RUB.
NICE.
SPANISH ONIONS,
RED SWEET BELL PEPPERS,
GREEN PEPPER,
SOME CILANTRO.
CUMIN.
FRESH THYME,
OREGANO, GARLIC.
A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC.
ANCHO CHILI POWDER,
HOT PAPRIKA, FRESH SAGE.
SAGE LOVES CHICKEN.
AND THEN...
THEN A LITTLE CAYENNE.
READY?
OH, NO.
NOW A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
JUST TO SMOOTH IT OUT.
GET ALL THAT GOOD STUFF
BACK IN THERE.
MMM, SMELLS AWESOME.
YOU CAN REALLY PICK UP
THE HENWAY.
THE WHAT?
WHAT'S HENWAY?
ABOUT 2 OR 3 POUNDS.
DA-DA.
OKAY.
I HAVE
TO TRY THIS NOW.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
GOOD?
NOW WE GET THE CHICKENS
OUT OF THE BRINE.
PAT THEM DRY.
ADD THE RUB.
RUB IT DOWN.
WE DO THE INSIDE
AND THE OUTSIDE.
MMM.
PUT SOME SERRANO CHILI SALT
ON THERE.
SERRANO CHILI SALT?
YEP.
LET'S TRY THAT.
WOW, THAT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT TO IT, HUH?
JUST ADDS THAT EDGE.
OKAY, TUCK THE LEGS IN,
NOW THE WINGS.
ARE THESE GONNA REST?
FIVE TO TEN MINUTES.
NOW WHAT?
OH, GEE, THIS IS
THE HARD PART.
THEY'RE READY TO GO
ON THE SKEWER.
AND HOW MANY
WILL IT HOLD?
TYPICALLY FOUR.
YOU KNEW SHE'S THE INTERNATIONAL
CHICKEN-STACKING CHAMPION,
DIDN'T YOU?
(laughing) PUTTING
THIS LAST GUY ON HERE
NICE AND SECURE, PUT THE HOLDER
THING ON--YOU GOT IT.
AND ONTO THE ROTISSERIE.
ONTO THE ROTISSERIE.
THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
THERE YOU GO. FIRE IT UP.
THEY COOK EVENLY,
KEEP ALL THE MOISTURE IN.
CAN'T BEAT ROTISSERIE.
I AGREE.
HOW LONG
ARE THEY GONNA GO?
ABOUT AN HOUR
AND 40 MINUTES.
LOOK AT THAT.
THEY ARE READY.
OH, I'LL GET IT.
OKAY.
JUST EAT IT LIKE FRED FLINTSTONE
CORN ON THE COB.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE'VE GOT THIS.
(whistles)
CHICKEN'S BEEN RESTING.
IT'S READY TO BE CUT UP.
LOOK AT THE PULL-APART,
TENDER,
OFF OF THE BIRD--
MMM.
JUST FALL-OFF-THE-BONE,
NICE CRUST ON THERE.
GOOD RUB--
THE RUB-A-DUB-DUB,
TENDER CHICKEN
TO GRUB. MMM.
NICE JOB.
YEAH.
(Leslie)
ROTISSERIE CHICKEN.
CRISP BUT STILL
VERY TENDER.
JUICY, TASTY,
REALLY GOOD.
THIS IS GOOD,
SOLID AMERICAN FOOD.
THIS IS MY BEST MEAL
OF THE DAY.
UNIQUE AND DIFFERENT FROM
ANYTHING ELSE IN THE AREA.
ROTISSERIE,
LOTS OF BACON,
HANDMADE DESSERTS--
FOR 14 SEATS?
14 SEATS.
YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
I DO.
NICE JOB.
NEXT STOP--WE'RE HEADING
TO MY HOMETOWN...
PICK UP--
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA...
I LOVE SEEING
THE KIDS.
TO HIT A SPOT...
(Guy) YOU THINK THIS
IS A GOOD OPPORTUNITY?
IT'S A GREAT
OPPORTUNITY.
WHERE GREAT GRUB
IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
WE'RE EATING BREAKFAST
COOKED BY MAYBE THE NEXT
GUY FIERI OF TOMORROW.
SO HERE I AM
IN SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA,
MY HOMETOWN.
NOW MY FIRST RESTAURANT
JOHNNY GARLIC'S
IS JUST ABOUT
A 1/2 MILE THAT WAY.
TODAY'S A VERY SPECIAL
TRIPLE "D" FOR ME,
'CAUSE I'M GETTING TO VISIT
A PLACE WHERE THE CHEF
WAS ONCE THE CHEF EDUCATOR
AT A JUVENILE DETENTION CENTER.
SHE'S NOW OPENED
HER OWN LOCAL RESTAURANT
WHERE SHE'S GIVING
UNDERSERVED YOUTH
AN OPPORTUNITY TO GET
THE EXPERIENCE AND EDUCATION
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
IT IS MY PRIVILEGE
TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO W.O.W.--WORTH OUR WEIGHT.
PICK UP,
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
THE KIDS' COOKING
IS AMAZING.
SCRAMBLED EGGS
WITH CREAM CHEESE AND LOX.
THIS IS MY MOM PENNY
AND MY DAD JIM.
THEY'RE THE ONES THAT TURNED ME
ON TO THIS JOINT.
GUY, THIS IS ABOUT THE BEST
BRUNCH I'VE EVER HAD.
AND THE PRICE...
POLENTA
AND CHICKEN SAUSAGE.
WELL, THAT'S UP TO YOU.
PEOPLE PAY WHAT THEY
FEEL THAT IT'S WORTH.
AND EVERYONE'S A VOLUNTEER,
FROM FOUNDER
EVELYN CHEATHAM...
I DO IT
BECAUSE I LOVE IT.
RIGHT DOWN TO SOME
AMBITIOUS, FOOD-LOVIN',
CULINARY APPRENTICES.
EVELYN'S THE CHEF.
MM-HMM.
YOU'RE THE SOUS-CHEF.
RIGHT.
YOU COOKED MY BREAKFAST
FOR ME TWO YEARS AGO.
OH, I STILL TALK
ABOUT THAT.
AND NICK WILKINSON'S
STILL WOWING THE BRUNCH CROWD.
ORDER UP,
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
HUEVOS RANCHEROS--
IT DOESN'T GET
MUCH BETTER THAN THAT.
HUGE, FRESH PULLED PORK--
DELICIOUS.
OKAY, PORK BUTT--
HOW ARE WE DOING IT?
WE'RE GONNA GIVE IT A RUB
WITH SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE IT
FAT UP?
YEP.
AS THE FAT COOKS OFF, IT RENDERS
DOWN ACROSS THE SIDES.
WE'RE GONNA ROAST IT
AT 500 ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
OKAY, NOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME ONIONS,
CARROTS.
SOME SWEETNESS
FROM THE CARROTS.
AND SOME CHIPOTLE PEPPERS.
DRIED JALAPEÑOS--
NICE.
AND NOW SOME WATER,
ALMOST TO THE TOP OF THE MEAT,
BUT YOU WANT
A LITTLE BIT SHOWING.
COOK THIS UNCOVERED?
YEP, 200 ABOUT 8 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT. WHAT ARE WE
ON TO NOW?
WE'RE MAKING
A PICO DE GALLO.
OKAY.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHOP UP SOME ONION.
GOOD KNIFE SKILLS,
MY FRIEND.
THANK YOU. THEN YOU'VE
GOT YOUR TOMATO.
SO NOW THE JALAPEÑOS.
YOU'RE GONNA GIVE
THOSE A MINCE.
YEP.
WANT TO GET THOSE NICE AND FINE,
SO YOU DON'T HAVE
THESE BIG NUGGETS OF FIRE
SITTING IN THERE.
NOW WE PUT A LITTLE
CILANTRO IN THERE.
AND THIS JUST GETS BETTER WITH
TIME, WHEN YOU LET THIS SET UP.
A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
SOME LIME JUICE.
NICE.
STIR IT UP.
SO YOU'RE GONNA LET THIS
SET UP FOR A FEW HOURS
BEFORE YOU SERVE IT?
YEAH, USUALLY OVERNIGHT
OR A COUPLE HOURS.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT. LET'S
GO MAKE SOME HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
LET'S DO IT.
SO THE PORK--WHEW--
IS DONE.
THE FINAL STEP FOR THAT
WAS IT GOT THE TOMATOES.
YEAH, CHOPPED TOMATOES.
PICO DE GALLO'S MADE.
WHERE WE AT?
THREE TORTILLAS
ON THE GRILL.
THE BEANS--WE SOAK 'EM
AND ADD CARROTS, ONION,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE PICO DE GALLO JUICE,
AND THEN LET IT SIMMER
ABOUT AN HOUR.
OKAY.
WE STRAIN 'EM OFF,
A LITTLE SALT,
AND THEN JUST LET THAT
SIT THERE WARMING.
PUT A LITTLE CHEDDAR
ON THESE TORTILLAS,
MONTEREY JACK ON IT.
BIGGER SELLER HERE--
THE HUEVOS RANCHEROS?
YEAH, THE HUEVOS
ARE, YEAH.
"HUEVOS" BEING THE EGGS.
(clicks tongue)
OLIVE OIL, A LITTLE BUTTER--
AND NOW THE EGG.
ADD SOME CHEDDAR CHEESE,
A LITTLE BIT OF JACK.
GIVE IT A FLIP.
ROLL IT.
LET THAT CHEESE MELT UP
AND TAKE THAT OFF.
TORTILLAS OVER HERE--
PUT THE BEANS ON.
NICE.
IS THIS ONE SERVING?
YES, SIR. NOW THE EGG.
PULLED PORK ON THE SIDE--
SOMETHING NICE LIKE THAT.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF OUR
PICO DE GALLO.
PICO DE ME-O.
AND JUST A LITTLE CILANTRO LEAF
FOR GARNISH.
I GOTTA TRY THIS
FIRST. MMM.
NICELY SEASONED, A LITTLE BIT
OF HEAT FROM THAT CHIPOTLE.
SOME OF THAT
PICO DE GALLO--OH.
HERE'S WHAT I LIKE--
YOU DO THE RIGHT STEPS.
YOU TAKE THE TIME--TWO DAYS
TO MAKE A SIMPLE BREAKFAST
YOU SEE ON A LOT OF MENUS,
BUT NOT HANDMADE
LIKE THEY DO IT
HERE AT W.O.W.
MMM. GREAT JOB, NICK.
THANK YOU.
HERE'S YOUR
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING THAT'S REALLY GOOD,
THIS IS IT.
IT'S PERFECT.
AND THE PLACE ITSELF--IT'S
JUST NOURISHING IN EVERY WAY.
SIDE OF POTATOES.
(Guy) YOU THINK THIS
IS A GOOD OPPORTUNITY?
IT'S A GREAT
OPPORTUNITY.
HUEVOS
FOR THE HUEVOS.
THIS IS
THE PLACE TO LEARN.
I FEEL LIKE
I CAN DO MORE IN LIFE.
(man) BREAD PUDDING.
I LOVE IT HERE.
IT FEELS GREAT TO BE HERE,
BESIDES THE FACT
THAT IT MAKES YOUR MOUTH
AND YOUR STOMACH REALLY HAPPY.
HERE'S YOUR BAGEL
AND LOX.
THE FOOD
IS PHENOMENAL.
THE BAKED GOODS HERE
ARE AMAZING.
YOUR LEMON BAR.
THE SCONES
ARE SO GOOD.
SCRATCH-BAKED BY ANOTHER
YOUNG CULINARIAN,
15-YEAR-OLD JESSIE HAYES.
HE'S A MASTER.
ALL RIGHT, JESS,
YOU AND ME, BUDDY.
LEAD ME INTO THIS.
THESE ARE ACTUALLY
NECTARINES.
NECTARINE SCONES?
YES.
WE'RE GOING TO START OFF
BY PUTTING THE FLOUR
IN THE BOWL.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR--
A.P.?
YES. WE'RE GOING TO ADD
SOME BAKING POWDER.
THE LEAVENING AGENT.
YEAH. SOME SALT
FOR FLAVOR. SUGAR.
ADD THE BUTTER. WE'RE JUST GONNA
MIX THIS UP A LITTLE BIT.
ABOUT THAT SIZE
IS A GOOD SIZE FOR BUTTER.
OKAY.
WE'RE GOING TO ADD
THE CREAM NEXT--HEAVY CREAM.
NOT SWEETENED, THOUGH.
NO. AND THEN FINALLY
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE FRUIT.
JUST GONNA BE A REAL LIGHT
FINAL MIX?
YEAH, JUST TO GET
THE CREAM IN THERE
WITH THE DRY INGREDIENTS.
LOOKING GOOD.
THAT'S IT. NOW WE'RE READY
TO FORM OUR DOUGH.
SPRINKLE SOME FLOUR
ON THE BENCH.
JUST GONNA TRY AND NOT WORK
WITH IT TOO MUCH.
WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU DO?
THE BUTTER WILL MELT,
AND IT WON'T BAKE
VERY WELL.
I'M GOING TO CUT IT
IN HALF.
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT
YOUR OTHER THREE
THAT ARE READY TO GO.
RIGHT. LAY IT OUT
ON A SHEET PAN.
PUT THEM IN THE FREEZER
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO WE DO NEXT?
BUTTER THE TOP. JUST KINDA
LIGHTLY SPRINKLE IT WITH SUGAR.
IT'S GONNA GIVE US A NICE,
BROWN, GOLDEN TEXTURE TO IT.
AND THEN JUST PUT 'EM
IN THE OVEN.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
BAKE 'EM AT?
425 FOR ABOUT 20
TO 25 MINUTES.
WHICH ONE DO YOU LIKE?
I KINDA LIKE THAT ONE.
ALL RIGHT. THEN I'M
GONNA TRY THIS ONE. MMM.
THOSE I LOVE.
IT'S TOTALLY MOIST,
NICE CRUNCH
TO THE OUTSIDE,
AND THE FRESH FRUIT
INSIDE OF IT.
I'M GETTING THE NECTARINE
IN THERE--SO SWEET AND JUICY.
(laughing)
IT WON'T FIT.
THAT WAS A FANTASTIC SCONE.
AND HERE'S YOUR SCONE.
IT'S REALLY BUTTERY
AND FLAKY.
YOU CAN REALLY TASTE
THE NECTARINE.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
GOOD JOB FOR THIS GUY, HUH?
15 YEARS OLD.
AND DOING IT ALL
ON HIS OWN TIME.
(Jessie) BREAD PUDDING.
THEY ALL ARE. SO I WANT TO DO
SOMETHING FOR THEM...
A LITTLE MINI W.O.W.
RESTAURANT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YEAH!
WELCOME BACK TO
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
HERE IN SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA,
MY HOMETOWN.
AND IT'S BEEN AN AMAZING VISIT.
WE'VE BEEN AT W.O.W.--
WORTH OUR WEIGHT--
WHERE KIDS ARE GETTING
AN OPPORTUNITY
TO LEARN THE INS AND OUTS
OF THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
THEY'RE DOING IT
ON THEIR OWN TIME.
AND THE VOLUNTEERS ARE DOING IT
PICK UP,
HUEVOS RANCHEROS.
LIKE FOUNDER
EVELYN CHEATHAM...
IT'S MY WHOLE LIFE,
AND IT'S 100% VOLUNTEER.
WHO'S TRAINED MORE THAN 100
YOUNG CULINARIANS
TO REALLY ROCK THE KITCHEN.
HE IS YOUR LEMON BAR.
GREAT-QUALITY FOOD.
REALLY DELICIOUS,
AND THE KIDS
GET TO HAVE INSTRUCTION
THAT IS REALLY, LIKE,
THE HIGHEST QUALITY.
HUEVOS RANCHEROS DOWN.
IT'S JUST A GOOD
ENVIRONMENT TO LEARN.
I LOVE SEEING THE KIDS.
I LOVE SEEING HOW THEY DEVELOP
AND GROW.
POLENTA
AND CHICKEN SAUSAGE.
IT OPENS MANY DOORS.
WE'RE EATING
BREAKFAST
COOKED BY MAYBE THE NEXT
GUY FIERI OF TOMORROW.
SO NOW IT'S MY TURN
TO PITCH IN.
LET'S BRING EVELYN
AND THE ENTIRE CREW FROM W.O.W.
OUT HERE SO THEY CAN SEE
THE DONATION
FROM THE GUY FIERI FOUNDATION--
THE W.O.W. CART.
YEAH!
SO EVELYN AND--AND ALL
THE TEAM HERE AT W.O.W.--
I MEAN, THE NAME
SHOULD BE W.O.W.,
BECAUSE I THINK EVERYBODY
WALKS OUT OF HERE GOING, "WOW."
WORTH OUR WEIGHT IN INCREDIBLE
EXPERIENCE FOR ME,
I THINK FOR EVERYBODY
THAT COMES HERE AND EATS,
FOR EVERYBODY
THAT'S BEEN WATCHING.
WE WANTED TO GIVE SOMETHING
TO MAKE YOU SAY WOW.
I GOT AN OPPORTUNITY
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
STARTING OUT SELLING PRETZELS
WHEN I WAS A KID.
I HAD A GREAT COMMUNITY
AROUND ME
THAT HELPED ME
BUILD THIS CART
AND GAVE ME THE OPPORTUNITY
TO GET INTO THE BUSINESS.
NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
SO THIS IS A DONATION
FROM ME
AND FROM MY FOUNDATION
FOR THE W.O.W. TEAM
TO SHARE ALL THE GREAT THINGS
THAT YOU DO AT W.O.W.
AND TO MAKE IT PORTABLE,
TO LET NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
TRY THOSE FANTASTIC SCONES
AND ALL THE BAKED GOODS
THAT YOU DO.
IT COOKS. IT COOLS.
THERE'S A 3-BAY SINK.
THERE'S A HAND-WASH SINK.
THIS, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS A LITTLE, MINI W.O.W.
RESTAURANT.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT'S SO GREAT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THIS IS GONNA BE
A WONDERFUL OPPORTUNITY
TO NOT ONLY SELL FOOD
AND MAKE MONEY FOR W.O.W.,
BUT IT'S GONNA BE
A GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU
TO INTERACT WITH YOUR COMMUNITY
AND FOR THEM TO SEE JUST HOW
INCREDIBLE YOU ALL REALLY ARE.
W.O.W. IS HAPPENING
BECAUSE OF ALL OF YOU.
WHEN YOU COME TO SONOMA COUNTY,
WHEN YOU'RE IN SANTA ROSA,
YOU GOTTA COME
SEE W.O.W.
(Guy) SO THAT'S IT
FOR A VERY SPECIAL TRIPLE "D."
BUT DON'T WORRY. THERE'S
PLENTY MORE JOINTS OUT THERE.
AND I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
BOOM!
OH! (laughing)
SCARE THE DICKENS OUT OF ME,
WHY DON'T YOU?
♪♪