HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP, FAVORITES...
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS UP.
WITH A TWIST.
THAT'S OUR
DUMPLING CUTTER HERE.
SHOT GLASS--
LIKE YOUR IDEA.
IN COEUR d'ALENE, IDAHO...
CHICKEN FRIED SKILLET'S UP.
THE 65-YEAR-OLD LANDMARK...
WE COME HERE ALL THE TIME.
WE LOVE IT.
TAKING COMFORT FOOD CLASSICS...
PECAN ROLL'S UP.
THEY'RE GIGANTIC.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
MMM.
AWESOME.
IN OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA...
AN ARTISAN DINER.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD CAFé...
EVERYTHING IS FANTASTIC.
SERVING UP BREAKFAST...
BISCUITS & GRAVY.
SOUTHERN STYLE.
(man) SHRIMP & GRITS
IN THE WINDOW.
MMM. PRIME TIME, MAN.
AND IN
MANCHESTER, CONNECTICUT...
HOT PEPPERS, JERSEY SHORE UP!
DREAM COMBINATION--
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE TRIPLE "D" FAN FAVORITE...
AWESOME. TO DIE FOR.
WHERE THE BURGERS...
GOT A CHIPOTLE.
ARE ONE-OF-A-KIND.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
IS THE CHIPOTLE CHEESE BURGER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN COEUR d'ALENE,
ABOUT 85 MILES FROM CANADA
IN THE PANHANDLE OF IDAHO.
NOW BACK IN THE DAY,
LOGGING WAS THE BIG INDUSTRY.
AND TO SUPPORT
THOSE HUNGRY LOGGERS
AND THEIR BIG APPETITES,
THEY NEEDED PLACES THAT WERE
SERVING GOOD OLD COMFORT FOOD,
LIKE THIS PLACE HERE.
BEEN DOING BUSINESS
FOR OVER 50 YEARS
AND IS NOW CALLED
JIMMY'S DOWN THE STREET.
CHICKEN FRIED SKILLET'S UP.
'50s DINER KIND OF PLACE.
IT'S LIKE
A DOWN-HOME COUNTRY KITCHEN.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY UP.
YOU GET A LOT OF FOOD.
THERE'S YOUR
CHICKEN FRIED SKILLET.
HUNGRY GUYS TO FEED,
A LOT OF LOGGERS,
CONSTRUCTION GUYS.
AND JUST ABOUT EVERYONE ELSE.
WE COME HERE ALL THE TIME,
AND WE LOVE IT.
PANCAKES, HASH BROWNS,
EVERYTHING.
SINFUL, STRAIGHTFORWARD
COMFORT FOOD, MAN.
SAME STUFF THIS JOINT'S
BEEN SERVIN' UP FOR DECADES.
(woman) BROCCOLI AND CHEDDAR
AND SCRAMBLED.
SO WHEN LONG-TIME RESTAURANT
VET JIMMY PURTEE
BOUGHT THE PLACE.
WANT MORE COFFEE?
HE KEPT WHAT WORKED...
IT'S ESSENTIALLY
THE SAME MENU
WITH A FEW
OF HIS OWN TWISTS.
WHERE DID THE RECIPE
FOR THE CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS
COME FROM?
FROM MY MOTHER.
AND NOW HEAD COOK
BEN McFARLAND'S
CRANKING 'EM OUT.
CHICKEN
AND DUMPLINGS UP!
THIS CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS
IS TO DIE FOR.
THIS IS THE CHICKEN
FOR THE CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS SKIN IT.
SKIN IT FIRST?
THIS IS THE FUN PART.
IT DOESN'T DRY OUT?
NO. I LEAVE
THE FAT ON IT.
FAT'S FLAVOR.
THROW IT ON THE SHEET PAN,
ADD OLIVE OIL.
JUST RUB THE OLIVE OIL
ON IT.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M GONNA SPRINKLE
THE ROSEMARY ON THERE.
SALT AND PEPPER?
NOPE.
LIVIN' ON THE EDGE, HUH?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN WE BAKE IT.
WITHOUT ANY SKIN?
WITHOUT ANY SKIN. IT SEASONS
THE CHICKEN WITHOUT HAVING
TO WORRY ABOUT ROSEMARY
NOT PENETRATING THE SKIN.
I'M DOWN WITH THAT.
ROAST OFF AT 350
FOR HOW LONG?
40 MINUTES.
(whistles) IT'S COOLED DOWN,
AND NOW YOU DEBONE IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
A LOT OF WORK
FOR CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
YOU KNOW, IT IS,
BUT IT'S WORTH IT.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER,
WHAT ARE WE ON TO NOW?
DOUGH FOR OUR DUMPLINGS
AND LITTLE BISCUITS
THAT GO ON TOP.
BOOM.
FLOUR, BAKING POWDER,
BAKING SODA.
LEAVENING AGENT,
SALT.
MIX IT IN THE HOBART.
AND I'M GONNA ADD THE BUTTER--
ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
THIS IS WHAT WE MIX TOGETHER,
KINDA EYEBALL IT AROUND HERE.
BUTTERMILK--ACID.
THAT HELPS ACTIVATE
THE LEAVENING AGENT.
JUST MIX IT.
SO IT'S JUST
A LITTLE WET, TACKY.
PAT IT OUT.
YOU DON'T WANT TO MESS
WITH IT TOO MUCH.
GIVE IT ONE QUICK,
LITTLE ROLL.
1/4 INCH.
JUST KNOCKED OVER
YOUR SHOT GLASS.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S MORE THAN A SHOT GLASS.
THAT'S OUR DUMPLING
CUTTER HERE.
I LIKE YOUR IDEA.
THIS IS THE SAME DOUGH WE'RE
GONNA USE FOR THE BISCUITS.
WE'LL CUT 'EM SMALLER.
YOU'LL CUT 'EM
SMALLER THAN THIS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE WORK IT.
HOW CAN YOU MAKE IT
ANY SMALLER?
WE USE WHAT'S
AVAILABLE.
THIS IS REALLY THE WAY
YOU GUYS DO THIS?
THIS IS REALLY
THE WAY WE DO IT.
I'M DOWN WITH IT, BUT, GOSH,
THAT LOOKS LIKE A LOT OF WORK.
NOW ONTO A GREASED SHEET
AND POP 'EM IN THE OVEN--
350 FOR 6 MINUTES?
YEP.
TIME TO MAKE
THE CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
(Ben) START
WITH OUR WATER,
CARROTS, DILL, CAYENNE PEPPER,
PARSLEY, BASIL, SALT.
WE'LL LET THAT COME
TO A BOIL AND COOK.
SO THAT'S BOILIN'.
WHEN THE CARROTS ARE SOFT,
WE'RE GONNA ADD ONIONS,
CELERY, AND OUR PEAS.
THROW IN OUR CHICKEN.
WE HAVE CHICKEN STOCK COMIN'
INTO THIS GAME AT ALL?
NOPE.
SO NO CHICKEN STOCK?
NO CHICKEN STOCK.
WE'LL LET IT BOIL
WITH THE CHICKEN FOR A MINUTE,
GET THE FLAVOR AND THE FAT
OUT OF THE CHICKEN.
AND WE'RE GONNA THROW
OUR DUMPLINGS IN THERE.
THAT JUST GOES
TILL THOSE PUFF UP?
BOIL IT
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES
TILL THE DOUGH COOKS,
AND THEN IT'S READY TO GO.
CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THIS.
THAT'S A NORMAL PORTION?
THAT'S OUR NORMAL PORTION.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR LITTLE BISCUITS.
THAT IS THICK.
MMM. I DIDN'T THINK IT WAS GONNA
NEARLY HAVE THE CHICKEN FLAVOR.
YOU GOT A TON IN THERE. LOOK
AT THAT BIG PIECE OF CHICKEN.
THE VEGGIES--MMM.
LOOK AT THE DUMPLINGS.
THERE RIGHT THERE--
FIRM BUT TENDER DUMPLINGS.
THEY'VE GOT TEXTURE.
MMM. DELICIOUS, MAN.
SCRATCH-MADE CHICKEN
AND DUMPLINGS--
YOU DON'T SEE THIS EVERY DAY.
IT'S GOOD EATS, MAN. MMM.
(woman)
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
THAT'S SOME REALLY RIGHTEOUS
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS,
DON'T YOU THINK?
YES, IT IS--
SOME OF THE BEST I'VE HAD.
PERFECT.
JUST WONDERFUL.
BREAKFAST BURRITO'S UP.
THE FOOD IS REALLY,
REALLY GOOD.
ANYTHING YOU WANT,
THEY HAVE.
CAKES,
SIDE OF BACON UP.
IT MAKES YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE IN YOUR OWN KITCHEN.
BACON-TOMATO
OMELET'S COMIN'.
IT'S A COMFORTING PLACE.
WITH A MENU TO MATCH.
WHAT IS COMFORT FOOD
TO YOU?
SOMETHING THAT YOU
CAN RELATE TO,
THAT MOM
USED TO COOK.
FROM BREAKFAST
BASICS...
BISCUITS AND GRAVY HERE
IS MY FAVORITE.
TO JIMMY'S MOM'S OWN
MONSTER CARAMEL PECAN ROLL.
THAT PECAN ROLL
IS FABULOUS.
ONE OF OUR FAVORITES.
AND NOW THIS ONE'S BECOME
KIM WOHLERT'S SPECIALTY.
(Kim) I STARTED OUT
WAITIN' TABLES.
(Guy) AND THEN THEY
FOUND OUT YOU COULD BAKE?
YOU NEVER TELL 'EM
THAT, MAN.
OH, HO HO.
A LOT OF PEOPLE COME IN
BECAUSE OF HER.
PECAN ROLL'S UP.
SO TELL ME ABOUT MAKING
THE PECAN ROLLS.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH MY YEAST...
OKAY.
MILK, WARM WATER.
MILK. HELP THAT YEAST,
GET IT GOIN'.
OKAY, WE'RE GETTIN' IT
DISSOLVED THERE.
I'M GONNA SLAP IN
MY SALT.
SLAP IN?
YES. SUGAR.
THAT YEAST
WANTS THAT SUGAR.
PUT IN THE EGGS,
CINNAMON...
OKAY. MINAMINAMIN.
'CAUSE I LIKE THE WAY IT MAKES
THE DOUGH LOOK SPECKLED.
SPECKLED.
WE'RE GONNA SLAP
OUR BUTTER IN.
A LOT OF SLAPPIN'
GOING ON.
OKAY, WHAT NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR FLOUR IN.
OKAY, SO YOU'RE DOIN'
A LOT OF EYEBALLIN' HERE.
YEP.
I WANT TO PUT
A LITTLE MORE IN THERE.
JUST FEELIN'
HOW TACKY IT IS?
CORRECT. ALL RIGHT,
NOW WE'RE GONNA KNEAD.
WHAT IS THAT
FANTASTIC NOISE?
IT'S THE OVEN.
THE OVEN PREHEATIN'
FOR THESE?
YEP. I THINK WE'RE GOOD.
STICK IT IN MY PAN.
PUT SOME BUTTER
IN THERE.
SMEAR IT AROUND.
AND DO THAT.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET IT PROOF?
ABOUT AN HOUR,
HOUR AND A HALF. BEHOLD.
PROOF-AGE-NESS.
LOOK AT ALL THAT.
IT'S ALL WARM.
LET ME SLAP A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS DOWN.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU HAVE
A GIGANTIC BABY HEART MONITOR
GOING AROUND HERE...
(rolls tongue)
IT'S CALLIN' MY DOUGH.
OH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH. LET ME FLOUR
THIS PUPPY, GET IT READY.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT
OF FLOUR DOWN.
WELL, I'VE GOT IT STUCK
ON THE TABLE BEFORE.
YEAH, NOT PRETTY.
THAT'S NO FUN.
I'M GONNA ROLL THIS WAY.
LOOK AT THAT
JUST WORKIN' OUT.
LET ME TRIM IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I JUST LIKE IT
A LITTLE MORE SQUARE.
THIS IS GOING TO THROUGH
THE FLAVOR-TOWN CAR WASH.
(makes swishing noises)
IT LOOKS LIKE
A BAD SQUID MOVIE.
WE'RE GONNA SPREAD
SOME BUTTER ON THERE.
I LIKE THIS.
IT'S ACTUALLY
KINDA SOOTHING.
ESPECIALLY WITH THE BABY
HEART MONITOR GOIN'.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
SO WE ADD BROWN SUGAR.
I MIX CINNAMON IN THERE,
AND I LIKE A LOT OF IT.
(whistles)
AND I JUST KINDA
SMEAR IT ON THERE.
DOESN'T IT LOOK LIKE A BIG
CINNAMON TOAST BLANKET?
AND I'M GONNA ROLL
THIS PUPPY TOGETHER.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
THIS THING
IS CRAZY BIG.
NOW WE'RE GONNA CUT IT
INTO OUR ROLL PORTIONS.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR CARAMEL SAUCE
TO PUT IN THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAN.
PUT IN OUR BUTTER,
CORN SYRUP.
ALWAYS MAKES
IT BETTER.
IT DOES. BROWN SUGAR.
COOK THIS DOWN TILL
THOSE CRYSTALS COME OUT.
IT'S GONNA START BUBBLIN' HERE.
THEN IT'S SCARY HOT.
I'M GONNA
CALL IT GOOD.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, LET ME GRAB THAT
UP THERE. AND NOW THE PECANS.
WOW.
200 BUCKS RIGHT THERE.
JIMMY, HE'S EATING THEM RAW.
THIS IS HOT NOW.
WE'RE GONNA POUR IN.
OKAY. OW.
I THINK WE'RE GOOD AND COVERED.
NOW WHAT I LIKE TO DO
IS MAKE A LITTLE SPOT FOR EACH
ONE MY LITTLE BUDDIES.
WHOA.
(laughing)
TUCK 'EM IN LIKE THAT.
THEY'RE READY TO GO
IN THE OVEN 20, 22 MINUTES.
YOU GUYS READY FOR THIS?
BETTER STAND BACK.
I'M STANDIN' BACK.
THESE PUPPIES ARE HOT.
(whistles) THEY'RE HUGE.
YOU'RE GONNA SEE
SOME ACTION.
LOOK AT HER.
LOOK HOW EXCITED SHE IS.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE PART.
(sighs)
NO WAY.
OW.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S HOT.
OH, REALLY?
(laughing)
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
SUCH GREAT TEXTURE TO THE DOUGH.
MMM. THE SUGAR AND THE CARAMEL
STARTS TO ALMOST CANDY UP
RIGHT ON THE OUTSIDE OF IT.
MM-MMM. THE PECANS ARE ROCKIN'.
AND IT'S NOT JUST
A LITTLE SPRINKLE-DINKLE.
THAT'S A FISTFUL OF PECANS.
AWESOME. NICE JOB.
HERE YOU GO, SWEETIE.
THERE'S YOUR PECAN ROLL.
REALLY MOIST. IT'S GOT A GOOD
CINNAMON-Y, CRUNCHY TOP.
THEY'RE GIGANTIC.
(woman) IT'S HUGE.
I MEAN, THAT THING
IS NUTS.
THERE ARE NUTS
IN THERE.
(imitates rim shot)
BISCUITS & GRAVY UP.
THE FOOD IS OUTSTANDING.
(man) IT'S ABOUT GETTING
A LITTLE TASTE OF COEUR d'ALENE.
IT'S THAT NICE HOMETOWN FEELING
TO IT.
FRISCO MELT, OMELET UP.
MOM WAS A GOOD COOK?
GREAT COOK.
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK SKILLET.
WOULD SHE BE HAPPY TO SEE
THAT YOU'RE RUNNING HER
MENU ITEMS NOW OR HER RECIPES?
I THINK SHE'D BE.
OR WOULD SHE BE GETTIN' ON YOU
FOR SHARING THEM?
NO, NO, NO, SHE WOULDN'T BE.
GOOD STUFF.
NICE JOINT, MAN.
UH-HUH.
UP NEXT...
SORT OF DOWN-HOME
WITH A SOUTHERN FLAIR.
WE'RE HEADING TO CALIFORNIA.
THIS IS JUST COMFORT FOOD.
FOR AN ENGLISH CLASSIC...
BUBBLE AND SQUEAK.
WITH A SOUTHERN ACCENT.
DUDE, GREENS FOR BREAKFAST?
MMM. OUTSTANDING.
I'M HERE
IN THE TEMESCAL NEIGHBORHOOD
OF NORTH OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA,
ON TELEGRAPH AVENUE.
NOW THIS RUN RIGHT UP
INTO U.C. BERKELEY,
AND ALONG THIS AVENUE,
PLENTY OF PLACES TO SHOP
AND A LOT OF GREAT
ETHNIC RESTAURANTS,
BUT NOT TOO MANY
ARE SERVING IT UP SOUTHERN STYLE
LIKE AUNT MARY'S CAFé.
BISCUITS & GRAVY.
THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
THIS IS
JUST COMFORT FOOD.
HERE YOU GO.
THEY HAVE SUCCOTASH HERE?
THEY DO.
ENJOY.
SORT OF DOWN-HOME
WITH A SOUTHERN FLAIR.
ORDER UP.
SORT OF LIKE
OWNER JACK STEWART'S FAMILY...
I'M FROM TEXAS. EVERYBODY ELSE
IS FROM TENNESSEE AND GEORGIA.
INCLUDING HIS FAVORITE AUNT...
IS THAT AUNT MARY'S
PICTURE OVER THERE?
IT IS.
THE INSPIRATION
FOR THE PLACE...
SHRIMP & GRITS
IN THE WINDOW.
AND THE MENU.
MMM.
(Jack) JUST A REAL HEAVY
SOUTHERN EMPHASIS.
AND HE'LL GO SOUTHERN
ON JUST ABOUT ANYTHING...
ALL RIGHT, LADIES.
EVEN THIS ENGLISH CLASSIC.
BUBBLE AND SQUEAK.
IT'S MASHED POTATOES
AND CABBAGE.
AND THIS
IS THE SOUTHERN VERSION.
POTATO CAKES
WITH GREENS IN THEM,
GRAVY OVER THE TOP.
DUDES, GREENS
FOR BREAKFAST?
THEY'RE AWESOME.
NOW WHAT ARE WE ONTO, BOSS?
THIS IS THE SOUTHERN GREENS
FOR THE BUBBLE AND SQUEAK.
OKAY, SO THE BUTTER.
CHOPPED ONIONS, GARLIC.
NICE TURN.
THE WATER, PUT A LITTLE
OF THAT IN THERE.
NECTAR OF THE GODS...
YEAH.
TABASCO, WORCESTERSHIRE--
THE OTHER NECTAR OF THE GODS...
A LITTLE CIDER.
CIDER VINEGAR...
MOLASSES--THERE WE GO.
(whistles)
PEPPER.
SALT.
HERE COMES THE GREENS.
THESE ARE COLLARDS.
COLLARD GREENS.
AND NOW WE GOT MUSTARD
STARTING TO CREEP IN.
THERE YOU ARE.
MESS THEM WITH THE TONGS.
DO MASSAGE THERAPY
WITH THOSE.
COVER WITH PARCHMENT PAPER.
AND THEM THOSE GO
FOR HOW LONG?
HOUR AND A HALF,
THEREABOUTS.
LOOK AT THOSE BAD BOYS
COOKED DOWN. OH, HO HO.
SHOULD WE TASTE THOSE?
LOVE GREENS. NEVER DID UNTIL
TRIPLE "D." NOW I LOVE THEM.
MMM!
WOW! THOSE ARE GREENS
WITH ATTITUDE. I LIKE IT.
(chuckles)
OKAY, NOW WE'RE DOING
THE POT LIKKER GRAVY.
YOU KNOW WHAT POT LIKKER IS,
RIGHT?
WELL, I'VE KNOWN A COUPLE,
BUT, YOU KNOW, USUALLY NOT
INVITED OVER MUCH AFTER THAT.
INTO THE POT.
THE COOK-OFF
OF THE COLLARD GREENS--
WE'LL MAKE A GRAVY
OUT OF THIS?
THIS IS IT.
OH, HO HO.
JUST BRING THIS BACK UP,
ADD A ROUX
TO THE BOILING POT LIKKER...
SOME 50/50 FLOUR/BUTTER.
YEAH.
LET IT SIMMER 30 MINUTES.
OKAY.
THEN YOU HIT IT
WITH SOME CREAM.
WHAT?
YOU'RE JUMPIN' THE GUN.
STIR THAT IN.
NOW I'LL TRY IT.
I WANNA WEAR THAT.
I WANNA HAVE THAT
AS MY HALLOWEEN OUTFIT.
"WHAT ARE YOU?"
"I'M POT LIKKER GRAVY."
NOW WE STRAIN THIS OFF.
HE'S SO QUICK. SO WHAT'S
THAT GETTING SERVED ON?
THE BUBBLE PATTY.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU REMEMBER
THOSE GREENS WE JUST MADE.
OH, WHAT GREENS?
WE'RE GONNA CUT THESE UP.
YOU BETTER KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WE GOT POTATOES. WE'RE GONNA
MASH 'EM UP A LITTLE BIT.
BUTTER?
SO WE GOT BUTTER,
SOME SALT.
ADD THE GREENS, AND THEN
WE JUST MIX 'EM IN.
THE DISH
IS LIKE EGGS BENEDICT.
GONE TENNESSEE.
PAN-FRY 'EM UP.
NICE PLACEMENT.
JUDGES COME UP WITH A 9.
AND WHAT IS THE SIMMERING WATER
ON THE STOVE FOR?
WELL, YOU GOTTA HAVE SOMETHING
TO GO ON TOP.
POACH A COUPLE OF EGGS.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW LET'S PLATE UP
THIS BUBBLE AND SQUEAK.
EGGS ARE ALWAYS TRYING
TO CRACK THE PARTY.
EXTRA GREENS.
THERE YOU GO!
KIND OF MAKE UP
FOR THE EGGS.
YEAH.
AND HIT A LITTLE
POT LIKKER GRAVY ON IT.
DON'T BE SHY WITH THAT NOW.
AND FINISH IT
WITH A BISCUIT.
IS THAT OVEN STILL ON?
WOW, TRICK EGG.
LOOK AT THAT POT LIKKER GRAVY
RIGHT THERE AND THOSE GREENS.
MMM!
THIS IS OUTSTANDING.
REALLY GOOD, MAN.
THOSE ARE GREAT GREENS.
MIX THEM WITH A LITTLE POTATO,
PUT A LITTLE PAN-FRY ON THEM,
THEN HIT THEM
WITH THIS POT LIKKER GRAVY--
THE SIGN OUT FRONT SHOULD JUST
SAY "HOUSE OF POT LIKKER GRAVY."
(chuckles)
MMM!
YOU'RE A MEAN, LEAN,
GREEN-MAKING MACHINE.
BUBBLE AND SQUEAK.
VERY FLAVORFUL. THE POTATO CAKES
ARE PARTICULARLY DELICIOUS.
BUT HOW ABOUT
THOSE COLLARD GREENS?
THEY ARE AMAZING.
YOU KNOW,
STUFF LIKE THAT'S
A LITTLE BIT HARD
TO FIND OUT HERE.
(scoffs) LITTLE?
WOW.
IT'S A LITTLE UNEXPECTED.
SO IS A LOT OF THE MENU.
HERE YOU GO.
IT'S SORT OF
A CRAFT CREATION.
TABASCO WOULD BE GREAT.
WHEN YOU COME HERE, YOU GET
A LITTLE BIT SOMETHING EXTRA.
MAC & CHEESE
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S HARD FOR ME TO LEAVE
THE RECIPES ALONE, YOU KNOW?
I DIG THAT.
I FIND SOMETHING.
I GO, "OH, YOU KNOW,
THERE'S OTHER THINGS I
CAN DO WITH THIS.
BASIL AIOLI.
LIKE LOADING
A B.L.T. WITH PESTO...
IT IS SUPER TASTY.
TOPPIN' A FRITTATA
WITH FRIED OYSTERS...
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
AND FOR THIS CLASSIC
NEW ORLEANS VERSION
OF FRENCH TOAST...
PAIN PERDU.
JACK'S DOING A HOMEMADE SYRUP
HE'S CALLING PAIN JUICE.
A TOTALLY UNIQUE CREATION.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE PAIN JUICE
FOR THE PAIN PERDU.
IT'S A SPICED WINE SYRUP.
RED WINE, WHITE WINE...
LIVIN' ON THE EDGE.
SUGAR...
HONEY.
A COUPLE OF CINNAMON STICKS.
STAR ANISE.
(whistles) THAT'S GONNA
BE INTERESTING. ALLSPICE.
AND CLOVES.
RED CLOVER, RED CLOVER,
LET GUY COME OVER.
LET THIS SIMMER 30 MINUTES.
CORNSTARCH--
MAKE A LITTLE SLURRY.
THEN WE'LL THICKEN IT UP.
WHISK THAT IN.
LET THAT TIGHTEN UP
AND STRAIN IT.
STRAIN IT.
GREAT.
OKAY, SO THIS IS THE WHISKEY
CREAM FOR THE PAIN PERDU.
EGGS.
WHISKED.
THEN WE ADD MILK.
THIS IS CREAM.
SUGAR, VANILLA.
NICE LITTLE SHOT OF THAT.
AND WHISKEY.
NICE. THERE YOU GO.
ALL OF IT.
(chuckles)
OKAY, THAT'S READY.
SO WE CUT UP OUR BAGUETTES,
PUT THEM IN THE PAN.
WE POUR THIS OVER
AND LET IT SOAK OVERNIGHT.
AND THEN?
WE COOK IT AND EAT IT.
FAVORITE WORDS.
(chuckles)
A LITTLE BUTTER IN THE PAN
FOR THE PAIN PERDU.
IS IT
REALLY PRONOUNCED PAIN?
YEAH. IT HURTS.
IT'S A FRENCH DISH--
"PAN" PERDU.
WELL, CAJUN FRENCH.
STAND IT UP AS BEST YOU CAN.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT MEANS,
THOUGH?
LOST BREAD.
ONCE WE GET A NICE BROWN ON
THIS SIDE, WE FLIP THEM OVER.
OKAY.
LET IT BROWN ON THIS END,
PUT THEM IN THE OVEN,
AND THEN YOU JUST HAVE
TO SIT AND WAIT.
JUST SIT AND WAIT FOR IT.
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
OKAY. WOW.
I THINK WE COULD EAT THOSE.
LITTLE VOLCANOES.
NOW WAIT--
THIS IS THAT RED WINE SYRUP
WITH THE SPICES.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
FRESH STRAWBERRIES
AND POWDERED SUGAR
GONNA CAP IT OFF.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
LOOK AT THAT CRUST.
MMM! DUDE, THAT'S A WINNER.
THE EXTERIOR CRUST,
IT'S SO UNIQUE FROM
THE OUTSIDE OF THAT BAGUETTE.
MMM. IT'S CRAZY.
AND THEN ON THE INSIDE, WHICH
IS NICE AND SOFT AND CREAMY.
IT'S LIKE FRENCH TOAST
MET BREAD PUDDING.
THE WINE SAUCE
IS OUT OF BOUNDS. HMM.
IT'S REALLY GOOD. HAVEN'T SEEN
THAT ONE BEFORE. NICE JOB.
PAIN PERDU.
IT'S JUST
SO DELECTABLE.
FLUFFY ON THE INSIDE--MMM--
VERY NICE, LIGHT CRUST.
(woman) I THINK I'VE ORDERED IT
EVERY TIME I'VE COME HERE.
NO.
YES.
ALL RIGHT, SO BUBBLE AND SQUEAK
AND PAIN PERDU.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
ONE OF MY ALL-TIME FAVORITES,
AND THAT'S GRITS.
SHRIMP & GRITS.
JACK'S WAY.
TABASCO GRAVY.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM! MMM.
(chuckles)
HERE YOU GO.
WE'RE BACK AT AUNT MARY'S CAFé
IN OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA...
ORDER UP!
WHERE OWNER JACK STEWART
IS GETTING BACK
TO HIS SOUTHERN ROOTS.
SHRIMP & GRITS
IN THE WINDOW.
MMM!
WITH HIS OWN TAKE ON GRAVY.
(Jack) TABASCO GRAVY.
IT'S SPICY. IT'S SMOKY
AND GOOD AND SOUTHERN.
(laughs)
ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
SO WE START OFF
WITH SHRIMP STOCK.
SHRIMP STOCK
THAT'S GOING FOR THE TABASCO
GRAVY FOR THE SHRIMP & GRITS.
THAT'S IT.
GOT IT.
SHRIMP SHELLS, FENNEL,
MOSTLY ENDS,
THE STALKS, OREGANO, ONION,
BAY LEAVES, CHOPPED GARLIC.
THAT AND SOME WATER--HOW LONG
YOU GONNA LET THAT SIMMER FOR?
30, 45 MINUTES.
AND THEN STRAIN IT,
AND THAT'LL BE GOING
INTO THE TABASCO GRAVY?
AND THEN WE MAKE THE GRAVY.
I'M GONNA ADD A FAIR AMOUNT
OF BUTTER TO THIS ONE.
THERE YOU GO.
I'M GONNA ADD CHOPPED ONION,
RED BELL PEPPERS,
SOME MORE FENNEL--SOMETHING
ABOUT FENNEL AND SHRIMP.
WORKS FOR ME.
WE GET THAT STIRRED IN.
LET THAT SIMMER
A LITTLE BIT, KIND OF DEVELOP.
OKAY.
WE WANT TO ADD GARLIC,
AND THEN THE REASON I ADDED
A LOT OF BUTTER TO THIS--
WORK SOME FLOUR IN.
AND MAKE YOUR ROUX
RIGHT OUT OF IT.
TRADITIONAL METHOD. OKAY.
THAT'S SOMETHING THEY DO
IN LOUISIANA.
BAY LEAVES, THYME,
OLD BAY.
WE TAKE THAT.
GET THAT MIXED IN, AND THAT
SHRIMP STOCK WE MADE EARLIER...
HERE IT COMES.
(pan sizzles)
HISS OF A SNAKE.
AND A LITTLE EXTRA ROUX.
I LIKE THAT TECHNIQUE.
ISN'T THAT GOOD?
JUST TO MAKE SURE WE GOT
ENOUGH THICKNESS IN THERE.
WE'LL LET THAT THICKEN UP
A LITTLE BIT, AND WE GOT--
TABASCO, HENCE THE NAME
OF THE GRAVY.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE BEFORE.
NOT MY FIRST RODEO.
TOMATO PASTE.
NICE LITTLE COLOR
THAT THAT.
PUTS SOUL IN THE DISH.
THERE YOU GO.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
LOOKS GOOD.
HIT IT WITH CREAM,
STIR THAT IN.
STRAIN IT OUT.
READY TO GO.
ALL RIGHT, NEXT UP?
MAKIN' GRITS.
WATER, SALT,
AND CRANK UP THE HEAT.
ADD OUR
STONE-GROUND YELLOW GRITS.
YOU CALLED ME UP FOR GRITS,
AND I AM A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL.
SIMMER FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF.
ADD FRESH BUTTER.
OF COURSE BUTTER HERE
AT AUNT MARY'S BUTTER BARN.
POUR THE GRITS
INTO THE PAN. HERE WE GO.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
PUT IT TOGETHER--
THE SHRIMP & GRITS.
A LITTLE BUTTER IN HERE.
OF COURSE. THE THEME TODAY,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS "GET A LITTLE BUTTER
IN HERE."
SMOKY BACON FROM TENNESSEE.
RED PEPPER AND WE GOT
THE PASILLA PEPPERS.
I'M NOT A BIG FAN
OF GREEN BELLS,
SO I USE PASILLAS.
NO, THEY GOT
AN INTERESTING FLAVOR.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE FIRE ON IT.
RED ONIONS,
WHITE WINE.
THAT'S A FIRE.
WE GOT ROASTED TOMATOES.
NOW WE DO THE SHRIMP.
HEY, GUESS WHAT? MORE BUTTER.
SALT AND PEPPER THERE.
AND WE'RE GONNA
FLARE THESE UP.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE CAN HIT THIS
WITH THE TABASCO GRAVY.
LOOK AT THAT. AND GRAVY.
THEN WE'LL FLIP
THE SHRIMP.
THERE YOU GO. SHE JUST CAME
OUT WITH THESE LAST WEEK.
I'M AN OLD-TIMER, YOU KNOW?
AND THE SHRIMPS ARE READY
FOR THE GRITS.
NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CHEESE CREAM.
GOT CREAM, GOAT CHEESE,
SOUR CREAM. MIX THIS TOGETHER.
LEMON JUICE AND A LITTLE SALT--
THAT'S READY TO GO.
OKAY, WE CAN START
PLATING THIS THING UP.
GRITS.
NOW THE GRAVY.
LAY OUT THE SHRIMP.
UH, HANG ON.
I'M JUST TUCKIN' 'EM
DOWN IN THERE.
AND THEN WE GOT GOAT CHEESE
CREAM, AND THAT'S IT.
OOH. DO YOU HAVE A SCALE?
4 POUNDS. 4 POUNDS.
THIS IS ENOUGH FOR THE WEEK.
SEE THAT?
MMM. MMM!
(chuckles)
MMM.
PRIME TIME, MAN.
LOTS OF FLAVOR.
BALANCED SPICE, GREAT GRITS.
MMM.
GOAT CHEESE HAS
A NICE LITTLE TANG TO IT. MMM.
WHAT I REALLY PROBABLY
APPRECIATE MORE THAN ANYTHING
IS THAT YOU LET ME EAT
RIGHT OUT OF THE SERVING BOWL
THAT WE BRING TO THANKSGIVING,
'CAUSE THAT'S JUST
A RIDICULOUS AMOUNT OF FOOD.
IS IT REALLY THAT MUCH?
PRETTY MUCH, YEP.
COME DOWN HERE
FOR YOUR GRIT FIX.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
(woman) IT'S GREAT.
THE GRITS ROCK, AND THE SHRIMP
HAD THAT GRILL FLAVOR, TOO.
NICE LITTLE SPICE--
NICE AND SEASONED.
HAD A LITTLE BITE TO IT.
REALLY FLAVORFUL. MMM.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
HEY, LADIES.
EVERYTHING IS FANTASTIC.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
AN ARTISAN DINER
IS WHAT I WOULD CALL IT.
IT'S A REALLY FUN
CREATIVE PLACE TO COME.
MMM.
WE LOVE IT. WE CHOSE THIS
EVERY WEEKEND.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
THAT'S WHY.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT A LITTLE
SOUTHERN FOOD IN OAKLAND?
DUDE, I'M GIVIN' YOU PROPS
ALL DAY LONG. NICE JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU. MMM!
NEXT UP...
WE'RE HEADING TO CONNECTICUT.
GOT A CHIPOTLE.
FOR FUNKY BURGERS...
I LOVE COMING
TO COREY'S CATSUP & MUSTARD
FOR THE AUNTIE LAURIE'S BURGER,
BECAUSE IT'S ON A PRETZEL BUN,
AND YOU CAN'T GET
THAT ANYWHERE ELSE.
TRIPLE "D" VIEWERS
JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
TO DIE FOR.
NOW I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE
OUT THERE
DIGGING UP LITTLE JOINTS
WITH BIG FOOD.
I MEAN, EVERY DAY I GET AN INBOX
FULL OF E-MAILS
FROM FOLKS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
TELLING ME
ABOUT THEIR FAVORITE JOINTS,
LIKE A BUNCH OF FOLKS IN
MANCHESTER, CONNECTICUT,
WHO ARE RAVING ABOUT THEIR
FAVORITE LITTLE BURGER JOINT
COREY'S CATSUP & MUSTARD.
I E-MAILED THE SHOW ABOUT
COREY'S CATSUP & MUSTARD
BECAUSE IT'S MY
FAVORITE RESTAURANT,
AND I LOVE THE FOOD.
THE MAN BURGER.
(man) THANK YOU.
I LOVE COMING
TO COREY'S CATSUP & MUSTARD.
IT'S NOT JUST
A TRADITIONAL BURGER JOINT.
GOT A CHIPOTLE.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ON THE MENU
IS THE CHIPOTLE CHEESEBURGER.
I LOVE COMING
TO COREY'S CATSUP & MUSTARD
FOR THE AUNTIE LAURIE'S BURGER
BECAUSE IT'S ON A PRETZEL BUN,
AND YOU CAN'T GET THAT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
THE FOOD HERE IS SO DIFFERENT,
AND IT'S ALSO SO GOOD.
I THINK I'VE TRIED JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
HE DOES AN AMAZING JOB
BACK THERE.
HE IS OWNER COREY WRY...
RODEO, PRETZEL, NO RANCH.
AND HE'S GOT A TON OF FANS...
WHO TELL ME HIS BURGERS
HAVE BECOME A LOCAL FAVORITE.
BLACK AND BLUE BURGER.
COREY IS A GENIUS.
HE CREATES
THE MOST AMAZING THINGS.
I THINK UNIQUE
AND DIFFERENT INGREDIENTS
AND DIFFERENT TOPPINGS
ON BURGERS
MAKE EATING OUT FUN.
HOT PEPPERS, JERSEY SHORE,
UP.
(man)
IT'S A DREAM COMBINATION.
YOU GET SAUSAGE
AND HAMBURGER TOGETHER.
AND YOU'RE GETTING BACON,
FRIED EGG, ROASTED RED PEPPERS,
AND ONIONS--REALLY GOOD.
TURKEY CALIFORNIA BURGER.
THERE'S SPINACH
AND BALSAMIC VINEGAR,
CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
IT'S JUST FULL OF FLAVOR
AND GOOD STUFF.
I'M MAKING A MESS.
(laughs)
I'M EATING
THE BLACK AND BLUE BURGER.
BLACKENED SPICE
GOING ON.
TONS OF BLUE CHEESE
AND ONIONS STRAWS--
DELIGHTFUL.
EXCELLENT.
HE'S EVEN TOPPING ONE
WITH BRISKET AND BACON.
7 NAPKIN BURGER.
ENJOY, GUYS.
SOMETIMES I LAY IN BED
AND FALL ASLEEP DREAMING ABOUT,
WHAT CAN I DO NEXT?
WHAT WOULD BE GREAT ON THIS BUN?
OR ON SOMETHING
THAT ISN'T A BUN.
CHIPOTLE BACON
DOUBLE STUFFED.
IT'S GOT THE MIXTURE
OF THE CHIPOTLE
WITH THE BLUE CHEESE
IN A WRAP.
(Corey) GOT A GOOD MORNING
AGAIN.
IT HAS WAFFLE, BACON, EGG,
A BURGER, AND THEN A MAPLE
DRESSING ON IT.
THE MAPLE MAYONNAISE--
IT'S WONDERFUL.
ON JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
THE SWEET POTATO FRIES
WITH MAPLE MAYO.
YOU WOULD NEVER THINK
THAT THEY'D GO TOGETHER,
BUT IT'S TASTY,
AND IT'S DIFFERENT.
AWESOME. TO DIE FOR.
BURIED UNDER CHEESEBURGER,
TABLE 12.
IF YOU'RE ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
THAT YOU JUST WANT
TO TRY SOMETHING DIFFERENT,
THEN THIS IS THE PLACE TO BE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT REALLY IS.
WE'VE BEEN
TO MANY, MANY BURGER JOINTS,
AND THIS
WAS THE BEST ONE EVER.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
THANKS FOR COMING TONIGHT.
IT'S A NICE LOCAL JOINT
THAT YOU CAN COME TO WITH
YOUR FAMILY AND YOUR FRIENDS.
I E-MAILED THE SHOW BECAUSE
I REALLY WANT OTHER PEOPLE
TO SEE WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT
AND WHY MY FRIENDS AND I REALLY
ENJOY COMING HERE SO MUCH.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF WE CAN'T PUT BUTTER
IN YOUR ICED TEA,
YOUR LUNCH IS FREE.
I'M JACK, AND THIS
IS AUNT MARY'S BUTTER BARN.
IT'S BUTTER FROM THE UDDER,
YOUR "UDDER" MOTHER.