Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and drives.
This trip...
It's the perfect sandwich.
...signature sandwiches.
Prime rib isn't
good enough by itself.
Let's smoke it
and put it on a po' boy.
Mmm.
In Denver, Colorado...
The food is fantastic.
...the former garage...
Regional favorites.
...doing it all fresh...
Spicy linguine,
going up in the window.
...even a Maine lobster roll.
Wow! Pretty impressive.
In Slidell, Louisiana...
WOMAN:
Cajun corn pudding.
...the neighborhood
favorite...
Very true
to Louisiana food.
...knocking out
authentic po' boys...
MAN: Shrimp po' boy dressed.
...and then some.
Side of corn pudding up.
Mmm.
That's corn quiche.
And in Indianapolis...
Corn cakes are on.
...the local café...
Mmm, it is so good.
...cranking out
ham and cheese.
Wow!
...with attitude.
Look at the size of this.
Mmm, this isn't
your average pork sandwich.
Thank you.
That's all coming up,
right here,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
I just love the joints
we visit on "Triple-D" --
I mean, where they started,
where they end up,
how it all began.
Now, I'm in the uptown area
of Denver, Colorado,
to visit a joint
that's in a building
that was operating
as an auto garage,
until the day it was converted
into a restaurant.
And the name?
Well, they get that
from a family-owned
hot spot in Boston
50 years ago.
And the menu?
Well, it's from everywhere
across the country.
This is
Steuben's Food Service.
Memphis Ribs
to the window.
The food is fantastic.
Regional favorites.
Green chili cheese up.
They travel around
the country,
and bring the best
of those regions to Denver.
Chicago dog going up.
Whatever hometown you're from,
they have it.
FIERI: Because when owners,
Josh Wolkon...
Enjoy.
...and Matt Selby...
Enjoy, you guys.
...started putting together
a menu
with
Chef Brandon Biederman...
Herb-roasted chicken up.
...it was personal.
Inevitably, we'd end up
talking about things
that we grew up eating.
Skirt steak.
And that was kind of
how the menu evolved.
It was right there
in front of us the whole time.
Fried chicken in the window.
You got
a great mix of food.
-From Southern...
I love the shrimp and grits.
-...to Italian.
-Spaghetti meatball up.
Classic recipe.
FIERI: Even this
New England standard.
Lobster roll and fries.
The lobster roll
is the real deal.
Lobster roll
in the window.
Get about 500 pounds
of lobsters
flown in a week.
Get your own
little plane for that.
Alright,
so give me the lowdown.
Okay, some boiling water,
salt it up.
Then, into the pool,
about 10, 11 minutes.
Lobsters are ready.
Put these in the ice bath.
-Stop the cooking process?
-Yeah.
BIEDERMAN: And these will cool
for a minute or two.
Lobsters are done.
This is going to be awesome.
Pull it out.
Pop off the claws.
Pop off the tail.
Breakdown the tail meat.
You don't want
to get squirted.
Like that.
Man...
Mess up my duds.
Ooh!
Coming into battle, folks.
Looks good.
Dice up the tail meat,
large chunk,
Split the claws.
Well, you got a lot of texture
coming out of the tail meat.
And it's real nice and buttery
here in the claw.
Nice balance.
Now?
Goes into a bowl.
And then we make
the lobster roll dressing.
Holy bucket of mayonnaise,
Batman!
Chopped onion. Celery.
Nice dice on that.
Yeah.
Lemon juice, paprika,
some salt, pepper,
and, we just mix it up.
Nice lobster roll.
Do you have these
shipped in?
Or does someone
make them here?
We do.
East Coast.
Nice!
Just doing a little bit
of clarified butter
on the flat top.
Let them toast up.
Alright.
Good healthy dollop
of dressing.
We mix them to order
each time.
Seems like it should be
a two-bunner.
No, you want them
overflowing.
I don't want to get it
on your hand, man.
Oh, it looks awesome.
[ Both laugh ]
Do I want a fork?
Do you guys think, at home,
I want a fork?
Absolutely not.
Is there anything
right here?
Right there? Anything?
You're good.
No, I'm good?
You're pretty good, yeah.
Just continue on
with the show?
Just keep going.
Awesome! Wow!
I want to be able
to taste the lobster.
I don't want to have
too much going on there.
That's real good.
And the fact that you guys
are doing this fresh,
pretty impressive, man,
nice job.
WOMAN:
Lobster roll with fries.
Just like a lobster roll
from Maine.
This is everything
with the salt air, you know.
Seriously,
all the food is so good.
It's a cool place to be.
Full rack of ribs.
It's got
a vintage feel to it.
FIERI:
Because it's a vintage place.
It's a revitalized garage.
My dad used to
bring his car here.
Dan's garage.
Automotive repair.
Hydraulic lifts,
cars out on the side.
WOMAN: Macaroni and cheese.
They turned it
into a restaurant.
And it gave life to
a wonderful old building.
Absolutely wonderful
for the neighborhood.
Etoufee
and hush puppies up.
Pretty casual,
very comfortable,
but it seems to all really
focus on doing great food.
Spicy linguine going
up in the window.
And it's cooked with love.
Here's your fries, guys.
The fries
are hand-cut here.
MAN:
Chopping fresh cut fries, chef.
That's one of the things that
they're known for, actually.
Fries up in the window.
I had the ribs today.
They definitely spend their time
making sure that
they're falling off the bone.
What's your favorite item
on the menu?
MAN:
Herb-roasted chicken.
You can tell these guys
slow-roast their chicken.
Do it real right.
What are we
going to make, chef?
BIEDERMAN: Herb butter
for the herb roasted chicken.
A lot of butter
for a lot of chicken.
We do everything big here.
Alright, softened,
unsalted butter.
Start the mixer.
Some garlic,
some shallots.
Chopped chives.
Some chive.
You know,
chive just keeps that color,
keeps its little form.
Some parsley.
Lemon juice?
Lemon juice, yes.
Nice.
Salt, pepper.
Turn it up to two.
And that's it.
And that gets a chance to marry
in a day's time --
Yeah. Okay.
Take that, and off we go.
That's it.
Alright.
So we're going to truss
and brine some whole chickens
before we roast them.
Truss and brine.
I like it.
Wings go back,
cross the legs.
The more you keep
this all together,
the better
it's going to cook,
and the more you're going
to hold in the juices.
These things are just
going to be full of flavor.
Yeah.
We put them in bus tubs.
Then let's make the brine
for the herb roasted chicken.
We get some brown sugar,
salt,
some whole cloves,
whole black peppercorns.
Go for it!
A little bay leaf.
And then a grip of water.
A grip?
About five gallons.
And whisk.
It goes over the birds.
Are we going to brine this
for about a day?
24 hours.
So they're brined
Give them a little shake dry.
Oh, this is awesome.
Olive oil.
Rub it in there.
Salt,
a little bit of pepper.
And then in the oven,
about 40 minutes.
350 in a convection?
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's rock and roll.
Pop it on
the cutting board, here.
Cut off the string.
Take it down at the leg.
Go down the tail bone,
hit the wishbone,
hit that knuckle.
There you go.
This is one portion?
Yes, sir.
Can't beat that.
You're saving the rest
of this carcass
for chicken stock?
Yes, sir.
Oh-ho!
We're just going to mark it
on the grill now,
brush it with some herb butter
that we made earlier.
Copious amounts.
Of course.
Nice.
Flip it over.
Brush it with some
more herb butter.
That's going to go
with mashed potatoes
and sautéed vegetables.
Okay, looking good.
Feeling good?
Yeah, feeling good.
Oh, look at that!
So you get the butter
confection onto the bird.
You also slathered it
on the veg.
Yeah.
Mmm.
Cooked to perfection.
Mmm!
I try to tell folks
this all the time.
It might say
roasted chicken,
but there's such
a wide spectrum...
of what it really is,
and what it really can be.
And right there,
my friend?
That's what it can be.
That's dynamite.
Out of bounds.
Marking herb roasted
chicken.
Tasty -- chicken has a nice
juicy, tender flavor to it.
The herbs really
stand out on there.
The flavors
are always good.
Cuban sandwich.
We always have something
different when we come here,
but we know it's always
going to be good.
They're passionate
about what they do,
and that's why
we keep coming back.
Chimichurri skirt steak
in the window.
Funky joint,
fun joint.
Save me a table.
I'll be back.
Right on.
Okay?
Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
Good times.
FIERI: Up next...
MAN: Cheese melted.
...we're heading
to Louisiana.
Come here because we know we're
going to get something good.
...where the prime rib...
Ohh!
...is smoking!
I can't believe
that whole thing
is going to be
on my sandwich.
♪♪
Now, there are two ways
you can get to the North Shore
of Lake Pontchartrain
coming from New Orleans.
You could take the Causeway,
end up in Mandeville.
Or, you could take
the Twin Span Bridge,
and end up in Slidell.
And if you're in Slidell,
I hear you've got to
check out a little joint
that's under
the big water tower
that's knocking out good,
old Louisiana comfort food.
This is LA Pines.
Bowl of gumbo up.
We come here 'cause
we know we're gonna
get something good.
Beef brisket po' boy up.
These po' boys
are delicious here.
WOMAN: Cajun corn pudding.
This is down home cooking,
and that's what people
come back for all the time.
Okay.
WOMAN:
Everybody comes here.
We know what's goes on
for the entire day.
Come here first,
get the down low
on what's happening?
Yeah, yeah.
FIERI:
Like folks have been doing
for almost 20 years.
Here you go.
Chef Jim Vandenburg
opened the joint.
Now his stepson Mike Murray
is running the show.
MURRAY:
Coming with the gumbo.
You just make it
right here?
That's it.
Scratch cooking.
All day.
Cheese melted.
FIERI: All of Jim's recipes...
Mama Jim's Debris up.
...and a few of
Mike's now, too.
He does his own smoking.
FIERI: Everything from
brisket and ribs...
On the grill.
...even prime rub,
served up Louisiana-style.
Prime rib po' boy up.
Prime rib isn't
good enough by itself.
Let's smoke it and then
put it on a po' boy.
It's delicious.
Smoked prime rib po' boy.
Big old rib.
Look at that thing.
We make a little rub for it.
Brown sugar,
we got a little chili powder.
Paprika.
I'm going to freak out
with the paprika.
Salt, white pepper,
and black pepper.
Cut of meat like this,
you don't need too much.
There's tons of flavor
in that fat right there.
Pour Worcestershire sauce
over it.
It helps the rub stick
and make sure it stays moist.
Pour some of
the rub on there.
This is going to cook down,
render off the fat,
then it's just
going to be good to go?
Better than good to go.
Wrap it up
and let it sit overnight.
Marinade for a bit.
Then we throw it
on the smoker.
Coming through. Coming through.
Stand back, folks.
We put it on the smoker,
fat side down.
And this is the mesquite
that you're running?
Throw a little bit on there,
to get the smoke rolling.
How long
do you let this run?
4 1/2 to 5 hours.
About 200.
That's it.
Now what are we making?
We're making a horseradish sauce
for the po' boy.
A little sour cream,
a little horseradish,
couple little chives,
little salt and pepper.
dash of Dijon mustard,
and mix that up.
Now, this is only
going to get better
with a little time,
correct?
Exactly,
as it chills out.
Good amount of
horseradish in my book.
Alright, so we go pull
the prime rib.
Ooh! I can't believe
that whole thing's
going to be
on my sandwich.
Wait until you see this.
There you go.
MURRAY:
This is the best part.
Look at that smoke ring,
right there.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Oh, that's horrible!
You don't want to
have any of that.
I think we should get
a 12 pack,
turn on the game,
get a few TVs.
Just whittle off
on this thing.
Yeah.
Stick that up in here.
It's like an angel singing.
That's it.
Let's make a po' boy.
Fresh bread, butter it,
and put it on the grill.
Stick a little bit of that down
in the au jus.
That's all you giving me?
There you go.
Let's take that bottom bun,
give you a little slop.
Sog that up, huh?
Yeah.
Fish her out of there.
Don't go losing none of it.
Yeah, I'm making sure now.
A little grilled onion,
couple slices of provolone.
horseradish sauce.
Prime rib po' boy.
With you soakifying
that bottom bun,
am I really going to be able
to pick this thing up?
Yeah, you've kind of
got to do a flip.
Mmm.
This thing rocks!
So you got a little
bit of sweet there,
a little bit of salt,
with the tang of
the horseradish,
the onions, the bread,
the smoke of the prime rib.
Look at that meat.
All that smoke.
How much is this?
$6.95.
What, per bite?
No!
For a 6" po' boy.
That's a four-napkiner.
Big sandwich.
Big flavor.
WOMAN: Here's your
smoked prime rib po' boy.
The best smoked flavor
of any meat I have ever eaten.
WOMAN: You can taste
the horseradish.
Brings out the flavor
in the meat.
It's very good.
FIERI: They do it right.
Do it right.
And a good price?
Good price.
MURRAY: Plating the ribs.
FIERI: Just the way
Mike's stepdad wanted.
I couldn't even restaurant,
when I started, you know.
Okay.
And now
he's packing them in.
Sweet potato fries
coming up.
MAN: Mike had a good job
of trying to hang on
to the traditional
New Orleans flavors.
WOMAN: Seafood gumbo.
FIERI: And what makes
Mike the proudest...
Coming to plate.
...is serving up his step-dad's
original recipes.
Side of corn pudding up.
And it is delicious!
What are we making?
Cajun corn pudding.
Start off with
husking our corn here.
Take all the silk off it?
Yeah.
You gonna roast it ahead
of time?
No. This is it.
Just going to put it
in the pan and fry it.
You see how hard it is
to get down into that bowl?
I'll show you
a little trick.
If you put that up
on top of there,
the corn is still going
to fall down into it.
Well, that is
kind of neat now.
Great idea.
Learn something every day.
Get your skillet going.
Olive oil
and our corn in there,
a little salt.
And it wouldn't be
Cajun corn pudding
without a little cayenne.
Couple of minutes in there.
Add a little bit
of bacon to it.
Let some of the fat
render out of it.
Check that really quick.
That's bacon.
We add onions
and green peppers.
While that's cooking down,
let's put the liquid mixture
together for the pudding.
Some eggs, cream,
and some milk.
Oh, this is quiche-like.
It's quiche-like.
Add a little nutmeg,
black pepper, little sugar.
That's not a little sugar.
That's a lot of sugar.
Then we add our corn.
Now whisk together.
A little Parmesan cheese.
Whoa!
Like the way you do that.
Cornmeal.
That all gets mixed together.
Alright, I'll butter
the casserole dish.
Put a little
breadcrumbs in here.
Shake it around, and give it
a little coat everywhere.
Then we'll
stir up in there good.
If you don't do that,
the cornmeal will
settle out in the bottom,
and it will be become
a layer.
Did you say "who dat"?
Who dat?
We add the mixture
to the casserole dish.
And then right in.
375 for how long?
About 45 minutes.
Alright.
Comes out like...
[ Whistles ]
Not sure if I'm
in quiche land.
Be brave.
Mmm.
That's corn quiche.
But outside of that,
there's a punch of flavor
in there.
You got
a little bit of heat.
That corn
is nice and sweet.
You've got
that fresh corn flavor.
And look at all of that --
the egg and the cream,
bunch of Parmesan cheese,
holds together.
That's a really nice side.
Nice and sturdy.
Nice job!
Thanks, man.
Cajun corn pudding.
MAN: It was delicious,
very sweet.
Yet it has a little
bit of spice to it.
And here's your
prime rib po' boy.
It's all good food.
Rib plate.
Potato salad. Baked beans.
WOMAN: I just love it here.
Very true to Louisiana food.
MURRAY: Coming to plate.
FIERI: Imagine Jim's
looking down here,
just proud as can be,
recognizing what a good job
you're doing.
You're still in here
working it every day.
And we've had a blast, man.
Thank you so much, Guy.
I appreciate it.
Thanks a lot for having us.
FIERI: Next stop,
we're heading to Indianapolis...
Really good food,
with lots of flavor.
...to pile on the pork.
Mmm, this isn't your average
pork sandwich.
♪♪
I'm here in the Broad Ripple
section of Indianapolis
to check out a joint
that's got all the makings
of a made-for-TV movie.
Let's see,
waitress meets line cook.
They fall in love.
They buy the restaurant.
And then, yeah,
they add meat
to the vegan-vegetarian menu.
I mean, you hear every day!
This is 3 Sisters Café.
Got an eggplant
on the rail.
Well, I'm a vegetarian.
Are you vegetarian
as well?
No, I like meat.
Pork's going on.
They can kind of
cater to everybody.
Look what I've got!
FIERI: That's exactly
what Moira Sommers...
I'm waiting
on my greens.
...and her partner
Alex Munroe wanted.
Just got on and --
We never looked back.
Here we go, guys.
Really good food
with lots of flavor.
You make everything
from scratch?
Absolutely.
MUNROE: Chili up.
FIERI: From vegan chili...
That's good.
Bacon is on.
FIERI: ...to barbecued
chicken with bacon...
I got a D'Nai
in the window.
...to this top seller...
Alex's take on
a ham and cheese sandwich.
...done with
a Southern spin.
I've never had kale
on a sandwich before.
Mmm, it is so good.
So what are we going
to make, brother?
The spice rub that we use
on the D'Nai pork sandwich.
All of this?
Paprika,
we're gonna go cumin,
white pepper,
oregano, coriander.
And who made
this concoction up?
Me. Kind of.
Chili powder,
black pepper,
granulated garlic,
sugar.
You got thyme.
A lot of it.
Yeah, a whole bunch.
Rosemary.
Some ginger,
just because we had some.
Nutmeg.
That's a generous
spice rub.
Blend them all
together by hand.
Because if you did it by foot,
that would really be weird.
Would be a little gamey,
you know.
Somebody's here
to play.
We need to set up
for a fresh ham.
Onions, we're going to
go celery, carrots.
Okay. A little garlic.
Liquid Smoke.
Some water.
We use the onions
to hold the wire rack up.
And our ham comes BRT.
"Bone rolled and tied."
In the fish net.
Put a little salt
and pepper on it.
Pork fish nets,
available at your Flavortown
department store.
We're going to put some rub
all over the top of this.
Very generous with that.
And there we are.
Foil on the top.
Now we're going to
go to the oven.
350 for about two hours.
And then another hour
with the foil off.
Okay, so it puts a nice
little crust on it,
a little bark.
Cool it.
And then to serve it?
Slice it,
and then braised kale.
Dude, when it comes to greens,
huge fan.
MUNROE: Well, we're going
to start with bacon.
Onions, garlic, cloves.
Liquid smoke.
A little red vinegar.
And, pretty good amount
of salt, pepper.
And then a whole
bunch of kale.
My mouth just went
into full Niagara.
Going to put some water
in there, and let this rip
about an hour and 15.
On to the pork.
Get the bun warmed up.
Good portion of pork.
Dunk it in au jus.
And the au jus,
what's in there?
The drippings from the pan,
plus a little bit of water,
and a little bit more
of the rub.
Just warm up in there.
Pile it up
with a lot of kale.
That is a wad of kale!
Wow!
And a little bit
of pepper jack cheese.
Little more au jus
on top of it.
Stick a lid on.
Takes about 20, 30 seconds
to melt the cheese.
Look at the size of this.
Side of au jus,
and we're there.
FIERI:
That's ridiculous!
Mmm, that is tender.
This isn't your average
pork sandwich by any means.
Melts in your mouth.
Really deep, flavorful,
you get a little bit of spice,
you get a little smoke.
Mmm!
Man, it's addictive.
The greens just make it.
Mmm.
You push the boundaries.
You take what people
are going to expect,
and you go beyond with it.
Really appreciate it.
Thank you.
I have the D'Nai
for you, my dear.
WOMAN: The combination of
the pepper jack cheese
and the kale
is just incredible.
The perfect sandwich.
Here we go.
Everything here
is fantastic.
Order up!
It is definitely the most
unique place in the area.
FIERI: On the first floor
of an old Victorian.
FIERI:
How old's the house?
It was constructed
in 1896.
You ready
for some goodies?
And everyone here
is really sweet.
Here we go, my babies!
It's like going to mama's
for Sunday morning brunch.
You got it.
FIERI: But here,
Alex is at the griddle...
SOMMERS: Here you go.
...scratch-making
old favorites...
I love their French toast.
It's fantastic.
...and house originals.
You got lemon corn cakes
in the window.
With lemon curd
and raspberries.
One of
my favorite things.
We're going to make
lemon raspberry corn cakes.
Can you say that
five times faster?
Lemon raspberry corn cakes
five times faster.
That's all I got.
Start with
a bunch of flour.
Then we're going
to go to cornmeal
and some baking soda.
Your baking powder.
Small amount of sugar,
lemon zest, eggs.
Margarine.
Water.
It gets us to
the consistenswe we want.
Consistent sweet.
Oh, consistent sweet.
Yes, Mr. Fudd.
Consistenswe.
Yeah. [As Elmer Fudd]
Be very, very quiet.
[ Normal voice ]
So we've got this.
What are we making now,
brother?
We're going to make
the lemon curd
for our corn cakes.
Water, lemon juice, sugar,
a little bit of salt.
We'll let this go
until it gets up to a boil.
Add liquefied corn starch,
Whip it together.
Next, egg yolks,
a little bit of lemon extract
at the end.
Onto the griddle.
Some liquid margarine.
About an even scoop of these.
Drop some raspberries
inside.
I love raspberries.
Go and flip.
Look at those!
Alright.
Oh!
Lemon curd.
Powdered sugar.
It's a pancake gone wild.
♪♪
Mmm! Really nice.
The texture of that cornmeal
going on with the crunch.
The little dab
of that powdered sugar
mixed in with that berry.
Look at that.
Fresh berries
right inside of that.
A little dunk o' curd.
♪♪
Mmm. The zing from that
really complements.
There's a little sweet
and sour going on in that.
Mmm. This is the kind of stuff
I like to eat for breakfast.
SOMMERS: Corn cakes with
some raspberries.
WOMAN: Really fruity.
The lemon curd
adds a lot of ting.
FIERI: The corn cake
with lemon curd --
is this common here
in Broad Ripple?
No, but it's common here
at 3 Sisters.
SOMMERS:
Here you go, sweetheart.
They've got a lot of that
kind of stuff on the menu.
Here we go, my sweets.
FIERI: Even for dessert.
Blueberry goat cheese pie.
The what?
Blueberry goat cheese pie
with some basil in it.
It's delicious.
Like nothing
I've ever had before.
FIERI:
When we come back.
Whoa!
♪♪
Here we go, guys.
FIERI: At 3 Sisters Café,
in Indianapolis...
And for you, my dove.
...owners Moira Sommers
and Alex Munroe...
Got a minute out
on the...
...are doing dessert...
Pie for you.
...their way.
Blueberry goat cheese pie.
It's like nothing
I've ever had before.
It's amazing.
We're going to
make some pie dough
for the blueberry
goat cheese pie.
The what?
Blueberry goat cheese pie
with some basil in it.
Start with flour.
All-purpose?
Yeah, and it's unbleached,
organic.
Salt, sugar,
a little bit of margarine.
Throw the lid on.
And since I guess we fall
into the dive category,
and it's broken,
we operate it this way.
Really? So you just jam
your knife in there?
Yeah.
10, 15, 20 seconds.
Just got a little bit of
flour gravel.
Cold water.
So you don't melt
the margarine.
Right, you don't want
to just gum it up.
As loose and moist
as you can get it
without beating it up
so much.
Right. That's really
all there is to this.
Put some plastic on it.
Let it rest.
Refrigerate.
It's about half an hour,
just so the gluten
kind of moves around.
Roll out some pie dough.
Just put down
a little bit of flour.
I won't get any on you,
I promise.
Yeah, please.
Kind of just work it out
until you get something
that's sort of round.
Start working it
with a rolling pin.
I like the way you roll.
Then I'm just going
to drop it in a pie
dish and trim it up.
Leave about 3/4-inch
around this.
Is this
your paring knife?
This 12" sword!
It's my only knife.
That's really about it
until we fill it with stuff.
With stuff?
Stuff. Pie stuff.
Coming up next,
pie stuff.
Start with
heavy whipping cream,
a little bit of brown sugar,
fresh basil.
little bit of flour,
and some goat cheese.
[ Imitates goat bleating ]
Did you hear that?
That is fresh.
Got an egg.
Now we're going to mix it up
a little bit, by hand.
It's alright
to leave little chunks.
You want
those little surprises.
Yeah, kind of.
I want you to hit different
bites when you eat it.
Then some blueberries.
[ Whistles ]
When you say "blueberry,"
you really mean it.
And then we're going to fill it.
You just scrape it on in.
Crazy. Wow.
Flatten it out.
Now we need to make
a topping.
And we do it with some
almonds and some sugar.
A little bit of
liquid margarine.
Get it stirred up a little.
Dig the mixture.
Right on top of the pie --
however much you want.
We're going to crimp it.
Don't crimp my style!
Nah, nah, just your pie.
So, I just kind of
fold and roll.
Pop this in the oven at 350
for about 30 minutes.
And then we're there.
So it cools down here?
Yeah. That's it.
Nice little crust on top.
I'm going to go ahead
and cut it,
and hopefully I can get one
of these things out of here.
And there it is.
You wanted some
more crunchy stuff,
'cause we went max on it.
Blueberries, goat cheese,
and basil, hmm.
Dude, whoa!
It's different.
Mmm, That pie rocks.
Thank you.
Seriously! Rocks!
Goat cheese and basil
party well together.
Wow! Contrasting
the sweet blueberry.
I mean, dude, that's
a full orchestra of flavor.
Well, you can see
my mouth is watering.
Look how my pie -- I mean,
I don't eat that much pie.
That's nice.
I want to see what
the next one you make,
with that beef jerky
and corn nuts.
Blueberry goat cheese pie.
WOMAN:
Kind of savory almost
with the goat cheese
and the basil.
It's like the best pie
I've ever had.
Your scramble.
Yummy!
Not matter what you order,
it's going to be great.
Alright, I got a ham
in the window.
It's all homemade.
D'Nai for you, my dear.
FIERI: Food that everybody
likes to eat,
made in not exactly
the most traditional manner.
You're putting on
the school today.
Nice job.
Thanks a lot.
Great stuff.
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to check
out all the recipes
from the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
And I'll see you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Okay, so...
MURRAY: [ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
Little hanging from the glasses
over there.