HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(woman) LOADED CHIPS.
FULLY LOADED...
MMM. HAVEN'T SEEN THAT
BEFORE ON TRIPLE "D."
IN NEW ORLEANS...
CRAB CAKES UP.
THE LOCAL LANDMARK...
IT'S A FABULOUS
NEIGHBORHOOD RESTAURANT.
THROWING CAJUN PORK
ON PIZZA...
MMM. IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND TAKING PO'BOYS...
(whistles)
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
NEAR INDIANAPOLIS...
GIOVANNI CHEESESTEAK.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT...
BRINGIN' A LITTLE BIT OF JERSEY
TO INDIANA.
LOADIN' UP CHEESESTEAKS...
(Guy) YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
WITH MEATBALLS.
MMM. THIS HAS GOT
A TON OF FLAVOR.
AND IN
BRIDGEPORT, CONNECTICUT...
GOT A BRUTAL WITH CHEESE.
THE TRIPLE "D" FAN FAVORITE...
IT'S JUST WICKED GOOD.
DOIN' BURGERS AND DOGS...
(woman) CHILI DOG UP.
YOU JUST HAD TO SHOW ME.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN NEW ORLEANS,
WITHOUT A DOUBT, ONE
OF MY FAVORITE DESTINATIONS--
I MEAN, THE PEOPLE, THE CULTURE,
AND, OF COURSE, THE GREAT FOOD.
NOW I'M ABOUT 3 MILES
FROM THE FRENCH QUARTER
IN AN AREA KNOWN AS MID-CITY
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT WAS DOWN
FOR FOUR AND HALF YEARS
DUE TO KATRINA,
BUT THEY'RE BACK UP AND RUNNING
NOW BETTER THAN BEFORE.
THIS IS KATIE'S.
CRAB CAKES UP.
BOUDREAUX'S
GOIN' ON THE RACK.
IT'S A FABULOUS
NEIGHBORHOOD RESTAURANT.
I COME HERE TO GET GREAT FOOD.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
HERE'S YOUR
CRAWFISH BEIGNET.
THE FOOD IS LOCAL FLAVOR.
THERE'S NO WAY
TO FAKE THIS.
(man)
PLATIN' GRITS.
NO NEED TO...
YOU BORN
AND RAISED HERE?
BORN AND RAISED.
SINCE OWNER SCOT CRAIG'S
BEEN DOIN' IT
ALL HIS LIFE.
WHERE DID YOU
LEARN TO COOK?
SELF-TAUGHT OVER THE YEARS,
JUST WORKIN' IN THE RESTAURANT
AND BAR BUSINESS.
I LOVE TO COOK.
SCOT JUST KNOWS
HOW TO DO IT.
FROM GRITS
AND GRILLADES...
(man) GOT YOUR
GRILLADE GRAVY.
THAT'S CREOLE FOR GRILLED VEAL
ON GRITS...
A CLASSIC,
FULL NEW ORLEANS DISH.
TO THOSE FAMOUS NEW ORLEANS
SANDWICHES CALLED PO'BOYS.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES
AND SHRIMP REMOULADE.
AND SOMETHING THEY CALL
COCHON DE LAIT...
CAJUN ROASTED PIG.
THAT SCOTTIE'S
THROWING ON PIZZA.
THE BOUDREAUX PIZZA HAS
THE COCHON DE LAIT ON IT.
THEY COOK THE PORK RIGHT
OUTSIDE HERE ON THE SMOKER.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE WE DOIN'
TO THIS PORK BUTT?
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE MAKIN'
A NICE, LITTLE DRY RUB FOR IT.
WE GOT A LITTLE ONION POWDER,
GARLIC--LOTS OF THAT.
OKAY.
CAYENNE.
THE HOT STUFF.
A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
SOME WHITE PEPPER, SALT,
CUMIN, PAPRIKA,
AND THEN THE OLD SECRET
INGREDIENT OVER HERE,
AND IF I TELL YOU,
I GOTTA KILL YOU, SO...
CAJUN SEASONING.
WE'LL JUST STIR IT UP,
AND I'M GONNA COME OVER HERE.
BONELESS PORK BUTT--
VERY IMPORTANT TO COOK IT
FAT SIDE UP,
'CAUSE THE FAT DRIPS DOWN...
IT'LL BASTE ITSELF
AS IT GOES.
AS WE GO.
AND THEN I MAKE
SOME BUTTONS.
VERY NICE.
I COME WITH A LITTLE PARSLEY
AND HIT IT WITH A LITTLE GARLIC.
MY DAD TAUGHT ME THAT
WHEN I WAS A KID.
I MISSED
ALL THE PARSLEY MOVES.
PUTTIN' ON THE RUB.
GENEROUS
APPLICATION.
RUB IT DOWN.
COME OVER
WITH OUR RUB.
FLIP IT BACK.
NOW OUT TO THE LITTLE SMOKER
ON THE STREET.
NICE.
LET'S ROLL.
I USED TO HAVE
A LITTLE UNIT LIKE THIS.
THAT'S HOW I STARTED
SMOKIN'.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
IT'S PERFECT FOR US.
THAT'S A REMOTE
TEMP CONTROL.
I WANT TO KEEP AN AVERAGE
BETWEEN 230 AND 250,
AND HOUR AND A HALF
A POUND.
(whistles)
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL. THAT'S
ABOUT 13 HOURS RIGHT THERE.
I HAVE TO USE A SPATULA
TO PICK THIS UP.
I'M SPOTTIN' YOU.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
LOOK AT THAT. HUH?
BONE COMES RIGHT OUT OF IT.
BEAUTIFUL.
GET A LITTLE PIECE
OFF THERE.
GOOD RUB, MAN.
NOW TO MAKE A PIZZA.
HERE WE GO--
START WITH OUR PIZZA DOUGH.
YOU JUST
RIP OFF CHUNKS.
YES. SOME FLOUR
ON YOUR TABLE.
AND THEN WE JUST KINDA
KNEAD IT A LITTLE BIT
AND GET IT IN A LITTLE CIRCLE
AND ROLL IT OUT.
I LIKE TO HAVE
A VERY THIN PIZZA.
SO YOU'RE NOT
REALLY CONCERNED
THAT IT LOOKS LIKE
NEBRASKA RIGHT NOW.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
I WILL TURN THAT
INTO A PERFECT CIRCLE.
THEN I HIT SOME SEMOLINA
SO IT WON'T STICK,
QUICKLY GET IT ON THAT PAN,
START FOLDING IT OVER,
TRY TO MAKE
A NICE CIRCLE.
THIS IS ABSOLUTELY,
UNQUESTIONABLY
THE MOST UNCONVENTIONAL METHOD
I'VE EVER SEEN.
I KINDA PINCH UP
MY ENDS HERE.
WE START WITH OUR
JIFFY-JANTY GARLIC BUTTER.
YOU KNOW, IT'S LIKE
A CREAMY BUTTER.
THAT'S REALLY STRONG
GARLIC FLAVOR.
AND THEN I COME WITH TWO
DIFFERENT KINDS OF CHEESES--
WHOLE-MILK MOZZARELLA.
AND THIS ONE
IS CALLED PROVEL.
IT IS VERY POPULAR
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
IT MELTS
ALMOST LIKE A BRIE.
NICE TANG TO IT--
THAT'S THE ONLY DIFFERENCE.
TONS OF FRESH SPINACH, SOME
REALLY NICE CHOPPED RED ONIONS,
AND THEN WE COME
WITH OUR COCHON.
AND YOU WANT TO SPREAD IT,
BREAK IT UP.
LAST BUT NOT LEAST, PUT A LITTLE
ROASTED GARLIC ON TOP HERE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
YOU RUNNIN' THIS AT?
ALMOST 400...
(speaking indistinctly)
AND THEN THREE QUARTERS
OF THE WAY THROUGH,
AND I TAKE IT OFF,
THROW IT ON THE ROCK
AND LET IT COOK
FOR A COUPLE MORE MINUTES
UNTIL IT GETS NICE AND CRISPY
ON THE BOTTOM.
READY?
SHE'S READY, BABY.
GOOD-LOOKIN' PIE.
ONE LAST THING
WE HAVE TO DO--
YOU GOTTA PUT THE JIFFY-JANTY
GARLIC BUTTER.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA CUT IT.
THERE YOU GO.
IMPRESSIVE.
THE PORK IS RED, THOUGH.
IT SHOULD BE,
NOT TOO MUCH SMOKE.
THE GARLIC BUTTER'S NICE,
UNDERNEATH THE CHEESE
AND THE SPINACH,
COMIN' THROUGH.
I MEAN, YOU TALK ABOUT CRACKER
CRUST. IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND I CAN TASTE THAT--WHAT'S
THE NAME OF THAT CHEESE AGAIN?
PROVEL.
YOU ROCKED THAT OUT.
NICE JOB.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
AND HERE IS
YOUR BOUDREAUX.
THE PORK
IS EXCELLENT.
(man) THIS IS GREAT STUFF
RIGHT HERE.
SOME CRAZY IMPORTED CHEESE
ALL THE WAY
FROM ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
OUTSTANDING.
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
BOUDREAUX UP.
THEY DIDN'T USED TO HAVE
PIZZAS BEFORE THE STORM.
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
2005...
BOOM.
7 FEET OF WATER,
AND EVERYTHING WAS WIPED OUT.
I LOST EVERYTHING.
SO SCOTTIE AND LONG-TIME
SERVER KATHERINE D'AQUIN
HAD THEIR WORK
CUT OUT FOR THEM.
AFTER THE STORM,
WE DROVE BY ALL THE TIME
TO SEE WHEN IT WOULD
OPEN UP AGAIN.
IT TOOK
FOUR AND A HALF YEARS,
BUT KATIE'S IS BACK.
JUST A NICE PLACE
TO GO HAVE FOOD.
KATHERINE'S
NOW PART-OWNER...
HOW WAS EVERYTHING?
AND SCOTTIE'S DECIDED
TO MIX THINGS UP A BIT.
ORDER UP!
EVERYTHING'S CHANGED HERE
SINCE KATRINA,
INCLUDING THE FOOD.
IT'S A COMBINATION
OF OLD AND NEW ORLEANS.
LIKE SCOTTIE'S NEW TAKE
ON THE CLASSIC PO'BOY.
BARGE IS UP!
IT'S FRENCH BREAD FILLED
WITH WONDERFUL
LOUISIANA SEAFOOD.
BY THE BOATLOAD.
VERY LARGE SANDWICH.
AS BIG AS A BARGE.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
TABASCO MAYO,
WHICH GOES ON OUR BARGE--
THE SANDWICH.
AND WE START WITH MAYO,
CALLED BLUE PLATE.
HABANERO TABASCO.
HE'S JUST DOUSIN' IT
ON THERE.
THEN WE GO WITH A LITTLE
GARLIC TABASCO SAUCE.
LAST ONE--SWEET AND SPICY
TABASCO SAUCE.
THEN YOU WHISK IT UP
TO A NICE, PINK COLOR.
AND THAT'S ALL GOOD TO GO
FOR THE BARGE.
NOT NEARLY AS INTIMIDATING AS--
WHOO, THERE'S THE HEAT.
YEAH?
(whistles) YOU GET THAT SWEET
RIGHT AT THE BEGINNING,
AND THEN...
(makes funny noise)
READY TO FRY
SOME SEAFOOD?
ALL OF THIS IS GOING
ON ONE SANDWICH?
WHAT HUMAN EATS THAT?
THREE OR FOUR OF 'EM.
WE START
WITH THE SHRIMP.
SEASONED FLOUR
OR JUST A.P.?
THIS IS JUST A.P. FLOUR.
WE DUST IT WITH THAT.
AND THEN WE ROLL IT
IN THE BUTTERMILK.
WHAT DO YOU GOT?
IT'S CREOLE SEASONING
AND BUTTERMILK
AND EGG, OF COURSE--
IT'S AN EGG WASH.
NOW THE CORN FLOUR.
AND WHERE DOES
THE SEAFOOD COME FROM?
RIGHT OFF OF OUR COAST.
THERE'S YOUR SHRIMP.
OKAY, SO THE OYSTERS
ARE FRESH.
THE OYSTERS
ARE FRESH SHUCKED.
AND WHAT KIND OF FISH?
THAT IS CATFISH.
FARM-RAISED?
HERE OUTSIDE
OF NEW ORLEANS.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S FRY IT UP
AND MAKE THE SANDWICH.
OKAY.
NOW WE GOTTA COOK
ALL THIS SEPARATELY...
(speaking
indistinctly)
'CAUSE WE GOT
DIFFERENT THINGS--
YOU'VE GOT
DIFFERENT SEAFOOD,
SO YOU HAVE TO COOK IT
SEPARATELY,
'CAUSE THEY DON'T ALL COOK
THE SAME WAY.
WHERE DO YOU WANT
ALL OF IT, BOSS?
RIGHT HERE, MAN.
THIS WORKS.
RIGHT UP TOP?
A LOT OF SEAFOOD.
THE VERY SPECIAL FRENCH BREAD
THAT MAKES THIS SANDWICH.
IT'S FROM JOHN GENDUSA BAKERY
HERE IN NEW ORLEANS.
IT'S BEEN AROUND SINCE THE '20s.
IT IS MY FAVORITE FRENCH BREAD.
I'M GONNA COME WITH A LITTLE
TABASCO MAYO ON BOTH SIDES.
'CAUSE YOU LIVE
ON THE EDGE.
THAT'S RIGHT. I LIKE THE MIXED
GREENS ON THIS SANDWICH.
START WITH A LITTLE CATFISH,
COME BACK WITH A LITTLE OYSTER,
COME BACK WITH
A LITTLE SHRIMP.
ME EAT
A LITTLE OYSTER.
YOU NOTICE,
I MIX 'EM ALL UP.
OYSTERS DOWN HERE IN LOUISIANA
ARE THE BOMB.
ALL RIGHT, THEN WE'RE GONNA COME
ACROSS WITH OUR ROMA TOMATOES.
AND THEN WE USE OUR PICKLES.
A PO'BOY ALWAYS HAS
LETTUCE, TOMATO, PICKLE.
AND THAT'S IT. THERE'S OUR
BARGE. WANT TO CLOSE HIM UP?
I'VE GOT TO PUT IT
ON THE BOARD.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
LET'S CUT IT. SO GO AHEAD
AND TAKE A CHUNK.
I GAVE YOU ONE
OUT OF THE MIDDLE.
MMM, A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
FROM THAT TABASCO.
THE BREAD'S GOT
GOOD BITE TO IT, GOOD CHEW.
THE MAYO'S ON POINT.
AND THE BREADING'S NOT
REAL HEAVY. LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A GOOD-LOOKING SANDWICH.
NICE JOB. REALLY GOOD.
HERE'S Y'ALL'S BARGE.
TERRIFIC.
VERY GOOD.
THE BIGGEST SANDWICH
I'VE EVER HAD.
HOW'S THE BARGE, SIR?
DELICIOUS.
GOOD, FRESH
LOUISIANA SEAFOOD.
OH, THIS IS ONE
OF OUR FAVORITE RESTAURANTS.
AND YOUR BOUDREAUX PIZZA.
IT'S A NEIGHBORHOOD RESTAURANT,
AND THAT'S HOW IT FEELS.
OH, YEAH.
GRITS AND GRILLADES,
SCOTTIE SPECIAL UP!
TO COME BACK
TO SOME PLACE
THAT KNOWS WHO YOU ARE
AND WHAT YOU LIKE.
THAT'S THE SPIRIT
OF THE FOLKS OF NEW ORLEANS
IS THAT YOU GUYS
REBUILT YOURSELVES.
IT TOOK YOU
FOUR AND A HALF YEARS,
BUT LOOK WHAT YOU GOT
GOIN' NOW, MAN.
THANKS, DUDE.
UP NEXT...
IN THE OVEN.
WE'RE HEADING TO INDIANA...
WILDWOOD CHEESESTEAK
AT THE WINDOW.
FOR A TASTE OF NEW JERSEY.
(Guy) THIS IS
THE REAL DEAL?
THE MOST AUTHENTIC
YOU CAN GET.
I'M ABOUT 25 MILES NORTH
OF DOWNTOWN INDIANAPOLIS
IN A TOWN CALLED CARMEL,
NOT "CAR-MEL"--
THAT'S OUT ON THE WEST COAST
WHERE I'M FROM--
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT'S
OWNED BY A NEW JERSEY TRANSPLANT
THAT'S COOKIN' UP REAL-DEAL,
OLD-SCHOOL,
EAST COAST CLASSICS HIS WAY.
THIS IS JERSEY'S CAFE.
CHEESESTEAK
AT THE WINDOW.
BRINGIN' A LITTLE BIT
OF JERSEY TO INDIANA.
EGGPLANT PARMESAN.
LIKE GOIN' BACK
TO NEW JERSEY
WITHOUT DRIVING
750 MILES.
(man) FANTASTIC--
PORK ROLL, EGG, AND CHEESE.
UNLESS YOU'RE FROM JERSEY, YOU
DON'T KNOW WHAT PORK ROLL IS.
ALL RIGHT.
(Guy) THIS IS
THE REAL DEAL?
THE MOST AUTHENTIC
YOU CAN GET.
'CAUSE WHEN JERSEY
NATIVE BLAIR LAING
MOVED TO INDIANA...
I NEED A PASTA,
PLEASE.
HE COULD'VE STARVED.
DID YOU FIND GOOD
EAST COAST CLASSIC FOOD?
NONE.
IN THE OVEN.
SO 13 YEARS AGO
HE OPENED HIS OWN JOINT.
WE GET A LOT OF JERSEY-ITES,
A LOT OF NEW YORKERS,
PEOPLE FROM DELAWARE,
PENNSYLVANIA.
'CAUSE HE'S GIVING 'EM
WHAT THEY MISS...
CHICKEN CLUB CHEESESTEAK.
LIKE 33 DIFFERENT
CHEESESTEAKS
LOADED WITH EVERYTHING FROM
JALAPEÑOS AND BARBECUE SAUCE...
CHEESESTEAK UP.
TO OLIVES AND EGGPLANT...
GIOVANNI CHEESESTEAK.
AND THIS ONE.
WILDWOOD CHEESESTEAK
AT THE WINDOW.
IT IS GRADE-A HEAVEN.
(Guy) MEATBALL SANDWICH
OR CHEESESTEAK SANDWICH?
CHEESESTEAK SANDWICH.
BUT IT HAS MEATBALLS IN IT
AND BLUE CHEESE.
WE'RE GOING TO START
WITH THE MEATBALLS.
BREADCRUMBS--A COMBINATION
OF OUR WHEAT AND VIENNA.
AND THEN WE'LL DO
THE EGGS.
HE'S GOT
THE ROCKY BALBOA...
(imitating Rocky)
OUI, ADRIAN.
(normal voice) THIS IS MY NONI,
MY GRANDMOTHER'S RECIPE.
GROUND BEEF.
80-20?
UH-HUH, BLACK ANGUS.
MILK.
GARLIC, PARSLEY,
LEMON PEPPER.
LEMON PEPPER,
OREGANO, SWEET BASIL,
ITALIAN PARMESAN.
NOW HOW ARE WE
GONNA COOK THESE?
IN THE SAUCE.
REALLY? COOKED DOWN
YEAH, THEY SIMMER.
PORTION 'EM OUT.
YEP, 2 1/4 OUNCES.
WHAT ARE WE DOING NOW?
WE'LL MAKE THE RED SAUCE.
AGAIN, THIS IS MY NONI'S RECIPE.
FIRE IN THE HOLE!
TOMATO SAUCE.
WE'RE NOT GONNA COOK
THE ONIONS AND THE PEPPERS?
NOPE.
SO THIS IS
STRAIGHT-UP NONI 101.
RIGHT. RED PEPPER.
GREEN PEPPER.
EVERYTHING IN RAW.
THIS MIGHT BE ONE
OF THE MOST UNIQUE RED SAUCES
I'VE EVER SEEN MADE
ON TRIPLE "D."
BASIL,
DRY BASIL.
A LITTLE OREGANO.
GARLIC POWDER,
LEMON PEPPER, AND PARSLEY.
SOME PARMESAN CHEESE.
WHOA.
WE NEED TO ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER TO THIN IT OUT.
LET THIS COME UP TO TEMP.
ADD SOME EXTRA-SHARP CHEDDAR.
GOING DOWN FOR SOME
OF THE SPAGHETTI FONDUE.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
TAKE THE MEATBALLS...
AND HOW LONG
WILL THESE COOK?
SIMMER FOR TWO HOURS.
SO MEATBALLS HAVE COOKED?
MEATBALLS ARE DONE.
OKAY.
SLICE 'EM.
SO LET'S TAKE
A LOOK AT THAT.
NICE, MOIST--
TASTY, DUDE.
THANK YOU.
START THE STEAK.
WE SLICE OUR OWN RIB EYES.
ALL RIGHT.
EACH DISH IS DONE
IN ONE PAN. PEPPER.
IF WE DO EVERYTHING IN HERE,
ALL THAT FLAVOR THAT COMES
OUT OF THERE JUST MAKES
THE STEAK TASTE BETTER.
MINERAL SALT,
MEATBALLS.
RED SAUCE IN THIS?
WE WANT A LITTLE SOMETHING
TO GO INTO THE STEAK.
BLUE CHEESE.
AND THEN THE SMOKED
PROVOLONE, OREGANO.
AND WE'LL PUT THAT
IN THE OVEN.
NICE ROLL.
WHERE DID IT COME FROM?
ASTORIA BAKERY,
ASTORIA, NEW YORK.
YOU HAVE THESE SENT
ALL THE WAY OUT?
THE ROLLS
HAVE TO BE DONE THERE.
THEY JUST DON'T
TURN OUT RIGHT HERE...
JUST CAN'T--
THE WATER, EVERYTHING ELSE.
TAKE THAT OUT OF THE OVEN.
SO GREASE AND ALL.
YEAH.
I LOVE THIS.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU'VE GOTTA BE
KIDDING ME.
THAT'S THE WILDWOOD.
HMM, THE CHEESESTEAK--
IT'S RIGHT THERE.
THE MEATBALL--ALREADY
I GAVE YOU AN "A" ON THAT.
THIS HAS GOT A TON OF FLAVOR.
LOOK AT THAT BLUE CHEESE.
IT REALLY TAKES YOU
IN ANOTHER DIRECTION.
IT TAKES A LITTLE BIT TO GET
USED TO, BUT IT'S GOOD.
YOUR THEORY ABOUT KEEPING IT
IN THE PAN
AND ALL THE JUICE COMIN' OFF
OF THAT RIB EYE...
MM-HMM.
MAN, I GOTTA SAY
AMEN TO THAT.
THE KICKER FOR ME
IS THE ROLL. NICE JOB.
THANKS.
(woman) WILDWOOD.
(man) IT'S A GIANT,
BUT IT IS REALLY TASTY.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S A FABULOUS
SANDWICH.
OOH, THANK YOU.
OH, MY GOD.
(woman)
YOU'RE WELCOME.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU TRY,
IT'S EXCELLENT.
(man) HOLY SMOKES.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS WONDERFUL,
ALL 3 BAJILLION
ITEMS.
ORDER UP!
I DON'T KNOW HOW HE DOES IT.
HE'S GOTTA BE HERE 24-7.
READY?
(Guy) HOW MANY HOURS
DO YOU WORK A DAY?
(Blair) 7:00 IN THE MORNING
TILL 11:30 EVERY NIGHT.
WHAT?
YEAH.
IT'S MINE.
(man) IT'S ALL SUPER FRESH.
HE MAKES HIS OWN BREAD.
YOU MAKE BREAD HERE
AS WELL?
YEAH. I FIGURE OUT
WHAT I HAVE TO DO TO MAKE IT
THE BEST SANDWICH.
CHICKEN SALAD CLUB.
CHICKEN SALAD,
BACON,
HOMEMADE BREAD.
OH, IT IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE GOING TO GO AHEAD AND MAKE
THE CRACKED WHEAT BREAD
FOR THE CHICKEN SALAD CLUB--
CRACKED WHEAT,
WATER, INDIANA HONEY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
WE USE AN APIARY HERE.
YEAH, BUT HOW DO YOU KNOW
THE BEE DIDN'T GO
OVER TO OHIO?
LET THE CRACKED WHEAT
COOK UP A LITTLE BIT.
SO THE CRACKED WHEAT OPENS UP,
SOFTENS. A LITTLE BIT OF YEAST.
MAKE THE YEAST SLURRY--
WARM WATER,
SUGAR, YEAST.
MMM, THAT SMELLS
AWESOME.
WILL PUT THE YEAST
IN THERE.
OKAY.
MILK. WE'LL ADD
THE WHEAT BERRIES.
FOLD THAT FLOUR IN.
WHOLE WHEAT.
ALL-PURPOSE.
LET IT RISE?
40 MINUTES.
PUNCH IT DOWN. OKAY.
NEXT PROCESS
FOR THE CRACKED WHEAT BREAD--
WE'LL ADD SOME CANOLA OIL,
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
MORE WHEAT FLOUR.
INCORPORATE THAT.
SO YOU LET IT GO
JUST ABOUT 10, 15 MINUTES?
WE WANT THE DOUGH
A LITTLE BIT TACKY.
OIL THE BOWL.
ADD THE DOUGH.
KNEAD IT.
WE'LL PUT THE TOWEL
OVER IT, LET IT RISE.
KNEAD THE DOUGH.
TURN IT INTO TWO LOAVES.
LET IT RISE AGAIN.
LOOK AT THESE.
THOSE HAVE RISEN UP NICE.
AND LOOK AT THE CRACKED
WHEAT ON THAT.
OKAY, SO INTO THE OVEN.
WE'RE USING CONVECTION--
315 FOR 30 MINUTES.
OH, LOAF-ALICIOUS.
YOU LET THESE REST UP,
'CAUSE IF YOU CUT INTO 'EM...
YEAH, WE'LL
LET 'EM REST.
RIGHT NOW,
THEY'LL JUST SHRINK.
RIGHT, THEY'LL
JUST FALL STRAIGHT DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO MAKE THE CHICKEN SALAD.
CHICKEN BREAST,
ROASTED SUNFLOWER SEEDS.
MMM. THAT'S A CALIFORNIA
THING RIGHT THERE.
ROASTED ALMONDS
AND ROASTED PECANS.
ALL THIS GOING IN THERE.
YEP. AND WE ALWAYS
USE FROZEN PEAS,
SO THAT WHEN YOU
MIX IT--RIGHT.
YOU MIX IT,
THEY DON'T SMASH.
AND THEN A GARDEN HERB
SEASONING.
LEMON PEPPER.
SOME CELERY SALT.
ALWAYS GOES GOOD
WITH CHICKEN SALAD.
FRESH PARSLEY.
CELERY.
AND WE ALWAYS USE
HELLMANN'S MAYONNAISE.
YEAH, YOU KNOW
YOU'RE FROM THE EAST COAST
WHEN YOU'RE QUOTIN' THAT YOU
ALWAYS USE HELLMANN'S.
LET IT SIT AND MARRY
SOME FLAVORS. MMM.
I LIKE THE PEAS IN THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH
FROM THE PECANS AND THE--
FROM THE ALMONDS.
GOOD CHICKEN SALAD.
ALL RIGHT.
SLICE 'EM UP, AND THEN WE'LL
MAKE THE SANDWICH. OKAY.
PUT SOME LEAF
LETTUCE ON THAT.
GENEROUS PORTION--
WHOA.
WE ALWAYS USE OUR BACON
AND TOMATOES, SWISS.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THE BREAD'S
RIGHTEOUS.
DOES IT COME WITH
A FREE SNOW SHOVEL?
YES, IT DOES.
CREAMY, NOT OVER-MAYONNAISED,
GOOD FLAVOR, NICE CRUNCH,
NICE, LITTLE SWEETNESS
IN THE PEAS.
YEAH.
CONGRATULATIONS. YOU HAVE
SUCH PASSION ABOUT THIS
AND ENTHUSIASM,
IT COMES OUT IN THE FOOD.
THANK YOU.
(woman)
CHICKEN SALAD CLUB.
THE BREAD'S GOT
SO MUCH FLAVOR,
AND IT ADDS A LOT
TO THE MEAL.
IT'S AWESOME.
AWESOME.
SO YOU THINK THAT'S
OFF THE HOOK?
WHEN WE COME BACK HERE TO
JERSEY'S CAFE IN INDIANAPOLIS,
WE'RE GONNA TRY
THE CHILI SPUDS AND...
LOADED HOMEMADE CHIPS.
THE CHIPS
ARE INCREDIBLE.
SEE YOU
IN A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS TRIPLE "D."
YEAH, YOU KNOW ME.
WE'RE IN INDIANAPOLIS
AT JERSEY'S CAFE.
WHAT ARE WE HAVIN' NEXT?
CHILI SPUDS.
NICE.
(man) IT'S A POTATO?
(man) A POTATO
WITH CHILI INSIDE,
LOADED UP WITH LETTUCE
AND SOUR CREAM AND TOMATOES.
(man) AS SOON AS YOU DIVE
INTO IT, YOU CAN TASTE
THE CHILI AND THE POTATOES,
AND IT'S GREAT.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE OUR HOMEMADE CHILI.
TOMATO SAUCE,
SOME WATER,
GROUND BEEF,
DARK CHILI POWDER.
(whistles)
LEMON PEPPER, CUMIN.
MEXICAN OREGANO.
YEAH, WELL, IT'S CHILI.
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
SO WE MIGHT AS WELL
ADD THE MEXICAN.
FRESH PARSLEY, GARLIC,
GREEN BELL PEPPER.
THIS IS EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL.
RIGHT. RED PEPPERS,
ONION.
A LITTLE CAJUN
IN THIS HERE?
YEAH, A LITTLE CAJUN
SOUTH JERSEY.
JALAPEÑO JUICE.
OUT OF ALL THIS,
A LITTLE JALAPEÑO JUICE.
YEP.
LET THIS COOK DOWN TILL
EVERYBODY BECOMES TRANSLUCENT,
THICKENS UP.
YEP.
NO BEANS.
DIG IT.
WE BAKE OUR POTATOES
WITH OLIVE OIL
AND A LITTLE
KOSHER SALT.
SO THERE'S THE KING KONG
OF POTATOES.
YEP. LET'S GO AHEAD
AND OPEN THAT UP.
DUDE.
LADLE THE CHILI.
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING.
(whistles)
A LITTLE MONTEREY,
SHREDDED LETTUCE.
LETTUCE ON IT?
YEAH. DICED TOMATO,
SOUR CREAM, CHIVES.
AND A TOUCH
OF CHILI POWDER.
YEAH, JUST A TOUCH.
SO HOW DO YOU GET INTO THIS,
START AT THE KNEE?
YEAH, I'D GO RIGHT DOWN
TO THE CENTER.
MMM. I WAS QUESTIONING
HOW THIS WAS GONNA COME OUT
WITH THE LETTUCE AND EVERYTHING
ON TOP OF IT.
MM-HMM.
BUT IT'S LIKE EATING
A GIGANTIC POTATO TACO.
THE CHILI HAS GOT
SO MUCH FLAVOR.
BIT OF THE LETTUCE, POTATO,
MEAT INSIDE OF THAT--MMM.
IT'S ENORMOUS.
I'VE NOT EVEN MADE A DENT.
ON A COLD DAY IN INDIANAPOLIS,
THAT'S A GO-TO RIGHT THERE.
YOU AND YOUR
CRAZY IDEAS, MAN.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
(man) CHILI SPUD.
(man) DELICIOUS.
YOU THINK IT'S GONNA BE COLD
WITH SEEING THE SOUR CREAM
AND THE LETTUCE,
AND THEN YOU GET UNDERNEATH IT,
AND IT'S GOT THE WARM,
HOT CHILI. IT'S GREAT.
IT'S DIFFERENT. IT'S UNIQUE.
I ALWAYS COME BACK HERE
BECAUSE I KNOW I CAN'T GET
SOMETHING QUITE LIKE THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
OOH, THANK YOU.
(Blain) EVERYTHING THAT'S
IN THIS PLACE IS ME.
YOUR STYLE, YOUR ATTITUDE,
YOUR RECIPES.
YEAH.
IN THE OVEN, GUYS.
AND THAT MEANS
SNAPS TO THE MAX.
LOADED CHIPS
IN THE WINDOW!
HOMEMADE CHIPS--
THEY'RE JUST INCREDIBLE.
YEP, HE'S SCRATCH-MAKIN'
THOSE, TOO.
WHAT ARE WE
MAKIN' NEXT?
HONEY-SWEET
BARBECUE SAUCE
THAT WE PUT IN
OUR LOADED HOMEMADE CHIPS.
EXTRA-THICK KETCHUP,
WATER, DRY MUSTARD,
FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
ALL RIGHTY.
A LITTLE LIQUID SMOKE.
FROM NEW JERSEY.
AND...
WORCES-CES-CES-CES-
CESTERSHIRE.
BLACKSTRAP MOLASSES.
THERE YOU GO.
ONION POWDER.
OH.
BROWN SUGAR.
FRESH SQUEEZED
LEMON JUICE.
AND A BOAT OF IT.
YEAH.
COUNTERBALANCE THAT SWEETNESS
IN THE KETCHUP.
YEP. PUT SOME LEMONS
IN THERE.
AND HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA LET THIS COOK DOWN?
UH, THIS WILL TAKE
ABOUT AN HOUR.
SO RUSSETS THIN-SLICED,
SOAKED IN WATER?
YEP. AND VINEGAR.
PULL THAT STARCH OUT
AND FRY 'EM UP...
YEP.
IN THAT LITTLE FRYER.
YES, SIR.
I LOVE THE WAY YOU MAKE IT
WORK. LOOK AT THAT.
RIGHT TO THE BRIM.
OKAY.
A LITTLE
MINERAL SALT.
SO EVERY TIME SOMEBODY ORDERS
CHIPS, THIS IS WHAT GOES DOWN?
YEP.
PEPPER.
DUDE, NO WONDER YOU WORK
EVERY DAY, ALL DAY.
YEAH.
TAKE THE HOMEMADE CHIPS,
TAKE OUR BARBECUE SAUCE.
MMM, NICE AND THIN.
SOME CHEDDAR-MONTEREY,
AND WE'LL PUT THAT
IN THE OVEN
JUST A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
TAKE THAT
OUT OF THE OVEN.
(sighs) NO.
YEAH. CRUMBLED BACON--
WELL, YOU HAVE TO.
IT'S SMOKED. IT'S BACON.
IT'S BARBECUE.
SOME GREEN ONIONS,
AND WE SERVE THAT
WITH THE HOMEMADE
BUTTERMILK RANCH DRESSING.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
GOOD?
MMM.
NICE AND THIN AND LIGHT.
A LITTLE TOUCH
OF THAT BARBECUE SAUCE.
IT HAS THAT FLAVOR
LIKE BARBECUE POTATO CHIPS.
AND THE RANCH--OF COURSE,
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN. MMM.
I HAVEN'T SEEN THAT
BEFORE ON TRIPLE "D."
(woman) LOADED CHIPS.
THE CHIPS
ARE INCREDIBLE.
(man) BARBECUE FLAVOR
AND THE WONDERFUL DIP--
VERY GOOD.
THEN WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND ADD CHEESE.
EVERYTHING'S MADE
WITH LOVE HERE.
WILDWOOD CHEESESTEAK
AT THE WINDOW!
LIKE THE MOM-AND-POP RESTAURANTS
BACK IN NEW JERSEY.
GOING IN THE OVEN.
YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE BACK IN JERSEY.
(man) ABSOLUTELY.
NICE JOB.
YOU'RE THE REAL DEAL, MAN.
THANKS.
NEXT STOP...
CAN I HAVE
A DOUBLE BACON?
WE'RE HEADING
TO BRIDGEPORT, CONNECTICUT...
LETTUCE, KETCHUP
ON THE NEXT ONE.
WHERE TRIPLE "D"
VIEWERS SAY...
THE BEST HOT DOGS
ANYWHERE.
YOU CAN'T BEAT THE DOGS.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
NOW YOU KNOW I DIG
A GREAT BURGER-AND-DOG JOINT,
AND SO DO A BUNCH OF FOLKS
THAT WROTE TO TELL ME
ABOUT THEIR FAVORITE
BURGER-AND-DOG SPOT
IN BRIDGEPORT, CONNECTICUT.
BUT GET THIS. IT'S ALSO
THEIR GO-TO SPOT FOR SEAFOOD.
CHECK OUT WHAT THEY'RE SAYIN'
ABOUT MERRITT CANTEEN.
ONE DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
MERRITT CANTEEN IS
AN ICON IN BRIDGEPORT.
CRAB IS READY.
THE BEST FOOD...
(man) ORDER UP.
IN THE FASTEST WAY.
BISON WITH FRIED ONION.
LET'S GO.
CAN I HAVE
A DOUBLE BACON?
(woman) IT'S FRESH.
IT'S COOKED TO ORDER.
HERE YOU GO.
I E-MAILED THE SHOW, BECAUSE
I LOVE COMIN' TO MERRITT CANTEEN
WITH MY FAMILY. WE'VE BEEN
DOIN' IT FOR GENERATIONS.
1/4 CHEESE
WITH BACON OUT.
MY GRANDPARENTS WENT HERE.
MY DAD WENT HERE.
ONE COLESLAW HOT DOG.
FROM THE TIME I WAS LITTLE,
I WAS COMIN' HERE.
JUST LIKE A LOT
OF THE REGULARS.
GOT A BRUTAL WITH CHEESE.
SAME GOES FOR THIS GUY--
OWNER JAY RODRIGUEZ...
I USED TO GET OFF THE BUS
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET.
BACK WHEN HIS DAD
RAN THE PLACE.
I TOOK OVER THE RESTAURANT
ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO.
I KEPT WHAT MADE
THE PLACE FAMOUS.
BACON AND A DOUBLE 1/4,
RIGHT?
WELL, IT IS STILL
THE SAME MERRITT CANTEEN
AS IT ALWAYS WAS.
LETTUCE, KETCHUP
ON THE NEXT ONE.
AND THAT'S JUST HOW
THE LOCALS LIKE IT.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
THEIR FOOD'S DELICIOUS.
(Jay) ALL-BEEF
COMIN' AT YOU.
THE BEST HOT DOGS
ANYWHERE.
AND TRIPLE "D" E-MAILERS AGREE.
DEEP-FRIED AND THEN PLACED
ON THE GRILL--
IT HAS, LIKE,
A NICE CRUNCH TO IT.
AND YOU CAN PUT ANY TOPPINGS
YOU WANT ON THERE.
BUT THE HOT TOPPING HERE...
(woman) CHILI DOG UP.
IS THE HOUSE CHILI.
IT'S, LIKE,
REALLY SPICY.
THE CHILI ON THE CHILI DOG
IS MY FATHER'S RECIPE.
WITH FRANK'S RED HOT,
TABASCO SAUCE,
AND CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
(woman) ONE CHILI DOG.
IT SETS YOUR MOUTH ON FIRE,
BUT IT'S GOT A GREAT TASTE, TOO.
THAT CHILI DOG
IS JUST KILLER.
MERRITT CANTEEN WILL ALWAYS
BE FAMOUS FOR HOT DOGS,
BUT NOW HE'S GOT
ALL THE DIFFERENT BURGERS,
THE SEAFOOD.
(Jay) ORDER UP.
LET'S GO.
YOU NEVER SEE SEAFOOD
AT A FAST-FOOD PLACE EVER.
I NEED THAT FISH.
AND IT'S BECOMIN'
A HUGE FAN-FAVORITE.
SOFT-SHELL CRABS ARE GREAT. WHO
WOULD EXPECT SOFT-SHELL CRAB?
IT'S REALLY MOIST AND CRISPY.
IT, LIKE, MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
NEW ENGLAND
CLAM CHOWDER...
CLAM CHOWDER UP.
WHICH IS
REALLY GREAT.
FISH AND CHIPS
IS DELICIOUS.
FISH UP.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY
LIGHT, CRISPY BATTER.
YOU CAN TELL
THEY MADE IT FRESH THAT DAY.
WE GET OUR FISH, UH,
DELIVERED FRESH,
AND WE FILLET THAT OURSELVES,
BATTER IT,
AND WE DEEP-FRY IT
TO ORDER.
(Jay) FISH PLATTER UP.
EVEN THE ORDER PROCESS
IS UNIQUE.
AND ALL ABOUT SPEED.
SO WE GOT A COLESLAW DOG
AND A SMALL DRINK.
FAST...
CHEESE
ON THAT BISON.
FASTER...
THAT WAS A DOUBLE CHEESE
AND AN EXTRA FRY.
AND PHENOMENALLY FAST.
COLESLAW, BACON DOUBLE,
FRIES.
THEY JUST YELL
TO THE CHEFS.
BACON DOUBLE CHEESE,
ORDER OF FRIES.
THEY REMEMBER
EVERYTHING.
FOR OVER 1,000 FOLKS
A DAY.
THEY NEVER GET
YOUR ORDER WRONG.
(woman)
ONE WITH THE WORKS.
I DON'T THINK THERE'S ANYBODY
FASTER IN THE COUNTRY.
(Jay) WHOLE BELLY UP.
IT'S HANDS-DOWN
THE BEST FOOD IN TOWN.
IT IS THE BEST FAST FOOD,
BUT I DON'T WANT TO CALL IT
FAST FOOD. IT'S MADE-TO-ORDER
FOOD, WHICH IS EVEN BETTER.
IT'S JUST WICKED GOOD.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(sighs)
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO NOW?
HARK, I THINK
I HEAR THE OVEN.
WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND PULL THE BREADS OUT.
"HARK, I THINK
I HEAR THE OVEN"?