HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(woman) BURGER'S READY.
SIGNATURE TWISTS...
WITH THEIR NAME ON THE PLATE
WRITTEN IN KETCHUP.
IN INDIANAPOLIS...
HI, YOU GUYS.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
VERY DOG-FRIENDLY.
WHERE THE LOCALS...
(barking)
ARE BARKING FOR BURGERS
AND BLTs...
MMM, THAT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
IN NEW ORLEANS...
MY PARENTS CAME HERE
50 YEARS AGO.
THE 116-YEAR-OLD LANDMARK...
IT'S QUINTESSENTIAL
FRENCH QUARTER.
PUTTING HIS SIGNATURE TWIST...
I'VE SEE TOMATOES
GO IN,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
TOMATO SAUCE.
ON A CREOLE CLASSIC...
(man) JAMBALAYA IN THE WINDOW.
WITH THE TOMATO SAUCE IN IT,
IT'S A NICE LITTLE SPIN.
AND OUTSIDE SACRAMENTO...
SHRIMP AND HEIRLOOM SALAD.
THE CORNER CAFé...
FRED IN THE KITCHEN,
SUCH A GREAT JOB.
CRANKING OUT CIOPPINO...
AWESOME.
AND PIES...
SHOULD'VE MADE ONE
FOR YOURSELF.
THAT TAKE A TRIP OUTSIDE.
I'VE SEEN
SOME BIG OVENS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE ON A TRAILER
THAT YOU TOW BEHIND A TRUCK.
THAT'S ALL COMING UP RIGHT HERE
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
I'M HERE IN INDIANAPOLIS
IN THE HISTORIC NEIGHBORHOOD
KNOWN AS MERIDIAN KESSLER--
IT'S CLOSE TO BUTLER UNIVERSITY
AND THE GOVERNOR'S MANSION--
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT I HEAR
NOT ONLY SERVES MAN
BUT HIS BEST FRIEND, TOO,
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU COME DOWN AND ORDER A MEAL,
AND THEY'LL FEED YOUR DOG.
AND TO JUST THINK,
I COULD'VE BROUGHT MY DOGS--
COWBOY, ROCK STAR, AND MEDUSA.
THIS IS THE BARKING DOG CAFé.
PICKUP, DOG PLATE, OLLIE.
(barking)
IT'S VERY DOG-FRIENDLY.
GOOD BOY.
EVERYBODY GETS THE LITTLE
BURGER FOR THEIR DOG.
JERSEY BOY.
WITH THEIR NAME ON THE PLATE
WRITTEN IN KETCHUP.
WE WOULDN'T WANT
TO GIVE THE WRONG DOG
THE WRONG DOG PLATE.
A SIGNATURE TWIST STARTED
BY DOG LOVERS JEFF GAHIMER...
PICKUP.
AND HIS WIFE MARY BETH...
HI, YOU GUYS.
A COUPLE
OF SELF-TAUGHT CHEFS...
CAN YOU SHAKE?
HAVING FUN WITH THE DOGS...
PUT IT UP THERE.
BUT SERIOUS ABOUT WHAT
THEY'RE SERVING THEIR OWNERS.
HI, JILL AND JOSH.
IT'S THE WAY THAT WE ALWAYS
COOK AT HOME BY OURSELVES,
FOR FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
(man) CHEESEBURGER.
OUT OF THIS WORLD.
SHARE A PIECE OF PIE TODAY.
CHERRY PIE--
VERY FLAKY CRUST.
HERE YOU GO.
WE DO EVERYTHING HERE
FROM SCRATCH.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE BACON
THEY'RE PILING ON THIS CLASSIC.
"BARK LARD" BLT.
"BARK LARD"?
KIND OF A PLAY
ON BARKING DOG
AND THE FACT THAT
IT'S LARD FOR BACON.
SO CATCHY.
BACON THAT IS HAND-CUT,
THICK, JUST DELICIOUS.
TO START CURING OUR BACON,
START OUT WITH FOUR SIDES.
PORK BELLY.
WE'RE GONNA GET IT DOWN.
SO MANAGEABLE SIDES.
EXACTLY.
SET THIS ASIDE.
AND WE'RE READY
TO MAKE OUR CURE--
BLACK PEPPERCORNS,
CARAWAY SEEDS.
LOVE THE CARAWAY.
THIS IS OUR OWN BLEND
WE CAME UP WITH--
FENNEL SEEDS, THYME,
ROSEMARY, BAY LEAVES.
GIVE THAT WHIRL.
(whistles)
NICE LITTLE FRAGRANCE
COMING OUT OF THERE.
YEAH, IT DOES.
PUT THE REST
OF OUR COMPONENTS IN--
KOSHER SALT, SUGAR.
SUPERFINE?
YEAH.
AND THEN OUR HERB MIXTURE.
WHY THE SUPERFINE SUGAR?
WHEN IT'S CURING, IT JUST
KIND OF MELTS INTO THE FAT
OF THE MEAT
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
LORD KNOWS SOME SUGAR'S
MELTED INTO MY FAT.
(laughs)
HOW LONG IS THIS DRY RUB
GONNA CURE THIS?
FIVE TO SEVEN DAYS.
WE'LL WORK IT
INTO THE MEAT.
IS IT GONNA GET SMOKED
AT ALL?
NO,
WE DON'T SMOKE IT.
WE'RE MORE
IN THE PANCETTA WORLD.
RIGHT.
PANCETTA'S ITALIAN BACON--
NOT SMOKED,
DONE IN THE SAME WAY.
TYPICALLY IT'S ROLLED UP.
THIS YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE FLAT.
RIGHT.
PLASTIC-WRAP IT, LET IT SET,
PULL OUT SOME OF THE MOISTURE,
BECAUSE THE SALT WORKS
FOR THE CURING PROCESS.
ABSOLUTELY.
PUT IT IN THE COOLER.
CURE IT FOR 7 TO 14 DAYS.
CURING YOUR OWN BACON--
YOU HAD ME AT HELLO.
(laughs)
NEXT STEP.
WE'LL UNWRAP THE CURED BACON
AND WIPE IT DOWN.
NOW IT GOES INTO THE OVEN
AT 200 DEGREES FOR 2 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE ALL CURED
AND COOLED OFF.
NOW WE SLICE IT.
THIS IS ALWAYS THE ONE THAT
STAYS IN THE KITCHEN
FOR THE CHEF.
WE MIGHT BE RELATED.
(laughs)
OH, LOOK AT THAT NICE, BIG, CUT-
IT-WITH-A-CAMPING-AX THICKNESS.
WE'RE LAYING OUT
THE BACON.
YEAH, WE'RE LAYING OUT
THE BACON HERE.
I'M GONNA POP IT
IN THE OVEN.
HOW LONG IS THAT
GONNA ROAST OFF FOR?
30 MINUTES. ALL RIGHT, WE'RE
GONNA DO OUR TOMATO JAM.
WE CAME UP
WITH THE TOMATO JAM,
BECAUSE TOMATOES ARE A LITTLE
HARD TO FIND IN INDIANA
IN THE WINTERTIME,
REALLY? WHY?
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
DICED TOMATOES, DICED ONION,
TOMATO PASTE.
AND THE RECIPE FOR THIS
CAME FROM...
JUST MESSING AROUND.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS APPLE JELLY,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
I'LL JUST GRAB THIS.
WELL, YOU GOT EVERYTHING ELSE
IN THERE BUT THE KITCHEN SINK.
YEAH, PRETTY MUCH.
GIVE THIS A STIR
AND PUT IT ON THE STOVE.
SIMMER ABOUT
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
WHAT ARE WE
ON TO NOW, BOSS?
BASIL MAYO.
GIVE THIS A CHOP, BASIL...
OKAY.
PINCH OF SALT,
SQUEEZE OF LEMON JUICE,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA WHISK THAT UP.
A LOT OF WORK
FOR A BLT.
WORTH IT, THOUGH.
BACON SHOULD BE GOOD TO GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WE'RE READY
TO BUILD THE BLT.
MULTIGRAIN BREAD...
SLATHER IT ON
WITH SOME BUTTER.
DOWN ON THE FLATTOP,
TOASTED MULTIGRAIN.
THAT GOES DOWN,
BASIL MAYO.
OF COURSE.
RIDICULOUS AMOUNTS OF BACON.
OUR TOMATO JAM, LETTUCE, 'CAUSE
YOU GOTTA KEEP IT HEALTHY.
THAT'S ALL THE LETTUCE
YOU PUT ON IT?
YEAH.
"BARK LARD" BLT.
MMM, THAT'S OUTRAGEOUS,
THAT TOMATO JAM.
YOU'LL NEVER WANT TO HAVE IT
WITH JUST REGULAR TOMATO AGAIN.
THE MULTIGRAIN'S A GREAT CHOICE.
THE MAYO IS A NICE LITTLE HINT.
MMM. I'M GLAD THAT LETTUCE
ISN'T GETTING IN THE WAY
THAT'D BE A COMPLETE
INTERRUPTION.
COPIOUS AMOUNTS OF BACON,
GREAT FLAVOR.
THE BACON OUTWEIGHS
EVERYTHING ELSE COMBINED.
I'D EAT THAT
OFF A MOVING TRUCK TIRE.
IF YOU'RE A BLT LOVER,
YOU GOTTA COME TRY THIS.
"BARK LARD" BLT--
WONDERFUL SANDWICH.
THE TOMATO JAM AND THE
MAYONNAISE REALLY BLEND NICELY.
THAT JAM IS...
IT'S JAMMIN'.
IT'S GREAT.
AND DON'T FORGET ABOUT
THE BACON. IT'S FABULOUS.
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
COFFEE-RUBBED DUCK BREAST.
THEY'LL TAKE SOMETHING
VERY SIMPLE
AND TURN IT INTO SOMETHING
YOU'VE NEVER TASTED BEFORE.
OR EVEN SEEN BEFORE.
(man) CHICKEN "LOLLIPOPS,"
HONEY-CHIPOTLE GLAZE.
MMM,
CRISP, MOIST, SIMPLE.
THESE ARE GREAT.
EVERYTHING IS JUST WONDERFUL.
(woman) BOWL OF CHOWDER.
IT BRINGS A LITTLE BIT
OF NEW ENGLAND-STYLE FOOD
TO INDIANAPOLIS.
'CAUSE MARY BETH, JEFF,
AND THE DOGS
SPENT A LOT OF TIME
BACK EAST...
HERE'S YOUR CRAB ROLLS.
AND BROUGHT THEIR FAVORITES
BACK WITH 'EM.
THERE'S YOUR OYSTER PLATE.
VERY SUCCULENT.
(man) CLAM PLATE.
LIGHTLY BREADED,
REALLY FLAVORFUL,
YOU THINK
YOU ARE IN NEW ENGLAND.
ESPECIALLY WITH THIS CLASSIC.
HERE'S YOUR SHRIMP ROLL.
THE SHRIMP WITH THE TOASTED ROLL
REALLY STANDS OUT TO ME.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE
WE MAKING NEXT, BOSS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE DRESSING
FOR THE SHRIMP ROLL--
MAYO, ADD OUR CHOPPED
FRESH TARRAGON.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
IT COMES IN
NICE AND FRESH.
LITTLE BIT OF TABASCO, SQUEEZE
OF LEMON JUICE, PINCH OF SALT.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA WHISK
ALL THAT UP REALLY GOOD.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR
SHRIMP THAT HAVE BEEN COOLED,
AND WE'VE GOT 'EM
CHOPPED IN HALF HERE.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF DICED GREEN ONION--
NICE COLOR IN THERE--
A LITTLE BIT OF DICED CUCUMBER,
A GOOD DAB OF
OUR SHRIMP DRESSING.
ALL RIGHT, WRAP IT UP.
LET'S GET IT GOING.
TOAST A NEW ENGLAND-STYLE
HOT DOG BUN...
I LIKE
THAT THEY'RE SHIPPED IN.
FRESH ORGANIC LETTUCE,
SHRIMP SALAD,
WHOA.
THERE WE HAVE IT.
THAT'S A BIG SERVING.
SHRIMP ARE COOKED PERFECTLY,
HAVE A LITTLE POP TO 'EM.
THREE CRITICAL FACTORS HERE--
GOTTA HAVE A REAL-DEAL ROLL.
CAN'T OVERCOOK THE SHRIMP, AND
DON'T OVERSEASON AND SAUCE IT.
AGAIN, GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANKS, MAN.
(man) SHRIMP ROLL.
(woman) IT'S SO FRESH,
JUST THE RIGHT TOUCH
SO YOU CAN REALLY
TASTE THE SHRIMP, MMM.
DELICIOUS.
PICKUP, DOUBLE CHEESEBURGER.
THIS PLACE IS AWESOME.
HI, KAYLIE.
I LOVE THE BARKING DOG.
CONGRATULATIONS,
A DREAM COME TRUE, RIGHT?
THANK YOU.
I WISH I WOULD'VE
BROUGHT MY DOGS.
(barks)
UP NEXT...
FLEUR DE LIS CHICKEN
IN THE WINDOW.
WE'RE HEADING TO NEW ORLEANS...
I DO LOVE THIS PLACE.
FOR A NEW TAKE...
I'VE SEEN TOMATOES
GO IN,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
TOMATO SAUCE.
ON AN OLD CLASSIC.
(man) JAMBALAYA IN THE WINDOW.
MMM. NICE JOB.
SO I'M HERE
IN THE FRENCH QUARTER
ON ST. PETER STREET
IN THE WORLD-FAMOUS CITY
OF NEW ORLEANS
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT THE PLAQUE SAYS
HAS BEEN OPERATING
AS A RESTAURANT SINCE 1894.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKING
OVER 116 YEARS.
THIS IS THE OLD COFFEEPOT.
FLEUR DE LIS CHICKEN
IN THE WINDOW.
VERY OLD NEW ORLEANS.
ONE LOST BREAD.
MY PARENTS CAME HERE
50 YEARS AGO.
(man) GRITS AND GRIDALLES.
IT'S QUINTESSENTIAL
FRENCH QUARTER.
I'VE GOT TWO
CRAWFISH SHRIMP CREOLE.
(man) YOUR FOOD'S READY.
(woman) THANK YOU.
THAT NEW ORLEANS FLAVOR
COMES THROUGH.
THANKS TO NEW ORLEANS CHEF
DUSTIN PALMISANO.
ORDER UP.
I ALWAYS WANTED TO BE A CHEF,
TO OWN SOMETHING.
AND HE GOT HIS CHANCE EARLY...
FLEUR DE LIS IN THE WINDOW.
TAKING OVER THIS JOINT WHEN
HE WAS JUST 24 YEARS OLD...
OPPORTUNITY CAME...
OPPORTUNITY SHOWED UP.
BUT, UH, IT SHOWED UP,
SLAPPED ME IN THE FACE,
AND I'VE BEEN
RUNNING WITH IT.
SERVING UP
NEW ORLEANS CLASSICS...
JAMBALAYA IN THE WINDOW.
HIS WAY.
GOOD TOMATO SAUCE.
TOMATO SAUCE?
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT DIFFERENT.
I REALLY LIKE THIS ONE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THIS IS GONNA BE
JAMBALAYA.
JAMBALAYA CAN BE MADE
WITH ANYTHING.
IT CAN BE.
WE MAKE IT WITH CHICKEN
AND ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL I DO IS TAKE
THE SKIN OFF OF IT.
BECAUSE...
LESS FAT.
GOT THE SKIN AND THE MAJORITY
OF THE FAT CUT OFF IT.
SALT AND PEPPER, FRESH CHOPPED
BASIL, A BUNCH OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT
OF CHOPPED ROSEMARY.
WAS THIS HOW YOU SAW IT GETTING
DONE WHEN YOU GOT HERE,
OR WAS THIS
YOUR IMPROVEMENT?
OH, THIS IS ALL ME.
WHAT TEMPERATURE ARE WE
ROASTING THIS OFF AT?
450.
450 FOR ABOUT...
45 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THE BIRD'S COOLED DOWN.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
SHRED THIS BIRD BY HAND?
I TAKE
THE BREAST OFF,
AND THEN I JUST
START PULLING.
AND HOW MANY CHICKENS
ARE WE DOING?
1 CHICKEN
FOR 8 CUPS OF RICE.
NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
NOW LET'S MAKE
THE JAMBALAYA.
OKAY.
BUTTER,
GET IT NICE AND HOT.
NOW THIS IS THE FAMOUS
CAJUN HOLY TRINITY.
ADD THE ONIONS,
BELL PEPPERS, CELERY.
YOU HAVE THE MIREPOIX,
WHICH IS A LOT OF TIMES
IN THE FRENCH FOOD,
WHICH IS THE CARROTS,
CELERY, AND ONION.
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING ABOUT
ADDING THAT PEPPER TO IT
THAT JUST STARTS
TO SET OFF THOSE FLAVORS.
DO YOU AGREE?
I DO AGREE WITH THAT.
OKAY, SO YOU
SWEAT THESE DOWN.
AFTER THAT,
YOU THROW IN
2 1/2 POUNDS
OF ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
THIS IS ABOUT AS CAJUN
AS IT GETS.
IT DEFINITELY HAS
AN EXTRA KICK IN IT.
SWEAT THE ANDOUILLE.
RENDER
SOME OF THAT FAT.
LET THE FLAVOR
SORT OF DRAW OUT OF IT.
MORE CHOPPED GARLIC,
FRESH BASIL, AND FRESH PARSLEY.
WHAT'S NEXT?
THE ROASTED CHICKEN.
OKAY.
NOW TRADITIONAL JAMBALAYA,
THAT'S MORE WITH BEEF STOCK
AND A LITTLE BIT
MORE WHITE IN COLOR.
I ACTUALLY USE
TOMATO SAUCE.
AND I GOTTA TELL YA,
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF JAMBALAYA
FROM A LOT
OF CRAZY DUDES.
THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I'VE SEEN ANYTHING CLOSE--
I'VE SEE TOMATOES
GO IN,
BUT I'VE NEVER SEEN
TOMATO SAUCE.
(laughs)
YOU AND I ARE BOTH GONNA GET IN
SOME TROUBLE IN THIS TOWN NOW.
THEN NEXT IS GONNA BE
THE FRESH CHICKEN STOCK WE ADD.
SO A LITTLE BIT
OF SIMMER.
AND THEN ADD YOUR RICE.
PARBOILED RICE--MEANS THAT IT
ACTUALLY HAS GONE THROUGH
A LITTLE BIT
OF ITS COOKING PROCESS.
YOU'RE GONNA LET THIS JUST GO
FOR A LITTLE BIT?
COOKS DOWN
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
EVAPORATE THE LIQUID.
YOU'RE GONNA STIR IT
PROBABLY, UH...
A LOT.
THAT'S IT.
NOW YOU GET ABOUT 14 OUNCES
OF JAMBALAYA ON A PLATE.
FINISH WITH PARSLEY.
(Guy) THERE YOU GO.
JAMBALAYA WITH TOMATO SAUCE.
MMM, GOOD LITTLE SPICE.
WITH THE TOMATO SAUCE IN IT,
IT'S A NICE LITTLE SPIN.
IT'S GOT THE THINGS YOU LOVE
ABOUT JAMBALAYA.
THE RICE IS COOKED BUT FIRM.
YOU GET A GOOD CHEW.
YOU'RE INTERSPERSED HERE
WITH ANDOUILLE
AND ROASTED CHICKEN.
THIS HAS GOT ITS OWN
LITTLE UNIQUE TWIST TO IT,
AND IT HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF YOUR ATTITUDE. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
HERE'S THE SHRIMP JAMBALAYA.
THEIR JAMBALAYA
IS DELICIOUS.
MMM.
FULL OF
CHICKEN AND SAUSAGE.
(woman)
JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF SPICE.
I'D SAY THIS IS PERFECT.
IT TASTES LIKE
IT'S HOMEMADE.
BLACKENED RED FISH
IN THE WINDOW.
THEIR FOOD IS INCREDIBLE.
(woman) ROAST BEEF PO'BOY.
IT'S THE AMBIENCE, THE DéCOR,
THE FRIENDLY STAFF.
IS EVERYTHING OKAY
WITH YOU ALL?
(voices overlapping)
YOU KNOW 'EM. IT'S LIKE
YOUR NEIGHBOR NEXT DOOR.
ESPECIALLY MISS PEARL.
CAN WE GET YOU ANYTHING ELSE?
I'VE WORKED HERE FOR 52 YEARS.
SHE'S DEFINITELY A BIG PART
OF THIS RESTAURANT.
SEAFOOD AND PASTA.
AND I HOPE YOU
FEEL THE LOVE TODAY.
SHE MAKES YOU FEEL AT HOME.
JUST LIKE
DUSTIN'S COOKING DOES.
NATURAL HERBS AND SPICES.
FRESH INGREDIENTS,
AUTHENTIC SEASONINGS.
IT TAKES WHAT YOUR MAMA COOKS
TO THE NEXT LEVEL.
EVEN YOUR MAMA'S CASSEROLE...
GREEN BEEN-ARTICHOKE CASSEROLE.
WITH FRESH GREEN BEANS
AND SCRATCH-MADE MUSHROOM SOUP.
THAT'S HOW
IT SHOULD BE DONE.
OH, HE ALREADY
ATE A PLATE.
YOU ALREADY ATE
THE GREEN BEAN?
THIS IS A SECOND ONE?
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
SO WE'LL START OFF MAKING
CREAM OF MUSHROOM SOUP.
OF COURSE, YOU ALWAYS
GOTTA START WITH BUTTER.
LET THAT SAUTé UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
SOME ONIONS, SOME BELL PEPPER,
ARTICHOKE BOTTOMS.
THE HEARTS
OF THE ARTICHOKES.
WITHOUT THE LEAVES.
GOT IT.
ONCE THAT SAUTéS UP
A LITTLE BIT,
YOU ADD A LITTLE BIT OF
CHOPPED UP CREMINI MUSHROOMS.
THOSE WILL REALLY BREAK DOWN
FOR THE FLAVOR.
ADD A LOT
OF CHOPPED GARLIC
I LIKE HOW THIS
IS STARTING OFF.
NOW SLICED CREMINI MUSHROOMS,
GREEN BEANS.
HARICOTS VERTS?
NICE THIN FRENCH GREEN BEANS
WITH THE STEMS OFF.
ONCE THAT'S SAUTéS OFF
A LITTLE BIT,
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CREAM SHERRY.
A LITTLE BITE THERE.
VERY IMPORTANT TO USE
HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM.
IT'S GOTTA BE 36% MILK FAT
OR MORE.
OKAY, WHAT'S UP NEXT?
WE LET THIS
START TO SIMMER,
AND RIGHT BEFORE
IT STARTS TO BOIL...
PARMESAN CHEESE.
A LITTLE PARMESAN CHEESE,
A LITTLE BIT OF...
CORNSTARCH SLURRY.
THAT'LL HELP
TIGHTEN IT UP.
A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
NOW WE'LL POUR THIS
INTO A PAN.
ALL THE GOODNESS
ON TOP.
YOU SMELL THAT SHERRY
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
PARMESAN CHEESE...
PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON IT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BREADCRUMBS.
AND WE'RE GONNA BAKE THAT OFF
IN THE OVEN AT WHAT TEMP?
400 FOR ABOUT
10 MINUTES.
GO.
NICE AND BROWN ON TOP.
FINISH WITH PARSLEY.
AND THAT IS IT.
I'M A HUGE
GREEN BEAN FAN.
MMM, THIS HAS GOT
HUGE FLAVOR.
THE CREMINI, OH, IT JUST MELTED
IN THAT CREAM SAUCE.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SHERRY, GOOD CRUNCH.
OLD-SCHOOL,
NOT CUTTING ANY CORNERS--
THAT'S HOW GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE
WAS MADE.
EVERY TIME I WAS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
THEY'D HAVE TO FIGHT ME OFF
WITH A STICK
NOT TO TAKE THE WHOLE
CASSEROLE DISH AWAY.
(laughs)
DUDE, GOTTA GIVE IT TO YOU
ON THAT.
THANK YOU.
TASTY, MAN, SERIOUSLY.
(Dustin)
GREEN BEAN-ARTICHOKE CASSEROLE.
I LOVED
THE GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
NICE AND CREAMY.
IT WAS A LITTLE CRUNCHY.
IT IS RICH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
VERY, VERY GOOD. MMM.
I DO LOVE
THIS PLACE.
WOULD THIS BE A PLACE
YOU COME BACK TO?
ABSOLUTELY.
OH, ABSOLUTELY, YEAH.
AND THANK YOU FOR COMING AGAIN
TO THE OLD COFFEEPOT.
FUNKY LITTLE JOINT, DUDE.
IF I HADN'T SEEN THE PLAQUE
ON THE GROUND,
I MEAN, YOU WOULD
JUST BLOW RIGHT BY IT.
YEAH.
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN.
I'M TELLIN' YA, LUCKY DUDE.
THANK YOU.
NEXT STOP...
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
WE'RE HEADING
OUTSIDE SACRAMENTO...
IT'S JUST
A REAL HOMETOWN FEEL.
FOR HANDMADE PIES...
(Guy) THIS THING
IS SMOKIN' HOT.
FROM A CUSTOM-MADE RIG.
WOW, GOTTA DIG THIS, MAN.
ABOUT 35 MILES
WEST OF SACRAMENTO
IS A LITTLE TOWN CALLED WINTERS.
NOW THEY'RE KNOWN
FOR GREAT AGRICULTURE,
ESPECIALLY THEIR WALNUTS.
NOW THERE'S ONLY A HANDFUL
OF RESTAURANTS IN TOWN,
AND ONE OF THE FAVORITES--
IT'S ACTUALLY
THE SECOND RESTAURANT
THAT WAS OPENED HERE--
IS KNOCKIN' 'EM OUT
WITH WOOD-FIRED PIZZAS
AND A MADE-FROM-SCRATCH MENU.
THIS IS PUTAH CREEK CAFE.
(man) GOT A MEDITERRANEAN.
THE BEST PIZZA YOU HAVE EVER HAD
IN YOUR LIFE.
FRESH ARTICHOKE HEARTS.
HOMEGROWN FOOD.
(woman) SHRIMP
AND HEIRLOOM TOMATO SALAD.
IT TASTES LIKE
YOU'RE EATING SOMETHING
THAT WAS PICKED THIS MORNING.
WE'VE GOT
A PROSCIUTTO PIZZA.
FRED IN THE KITCHEN,
SUCH A GREAT JOB.
THAT'D BE CHEF FRED REYES...
WESTERN BURGER COMING UP.
WHO'S GOT 35 YEARS
IN THE BIZ...
SMOKED SALMON APPETIZER.
FROM WHITE-TABLECLOTH JOINTS...
GREEK CHICKEN SALAD.
TO MOM-AND-POPS...
BURGER COMING UP.
AND NOW HE'S MAKING HIS MARK
ON PUTAH CREEK...
FIRST THING
I THOUGHT ABOUT
WAS DOING EVERYTHING FROM
SCRATCH AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE.
AND IT'S WORKING...
PAELLA UP IN THE WINDOW.
ABSOLUTELY DIVINE.
BRICK CHICKEN.
THE FIRE-ROASTED CHICKEN
IS FANTASTIC.
AND FRED'S SCRATCH-MADE TAKE
ON A SAN FRANCISCO CLASSIC...
CIOPPINO
UP IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S FULL OF SEAFOOD.
IT'S THE PERFECT BLEND.
WE'RE GONNA DO THE FIRST PROCESS
OF THE CIOPPINO,
HOMEMADE FISH STOCK--
FRESH FISH BONES...
HALIBUT YOU'VE BROKEN DOWN?
YES, AND SHRIMP SHELLS.
I GOT SOME LOBSTER PASTE...
OKAY.
CELERY, CARROTS, ONIONS...
SO A LITTLE MIREPOIX
GOING IN.
PARSLEY STEMS...
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
YES, SIR, FRESH GARLIC,
BAY LEAVES, SOME PEPPERCORN,
AND CLAM BASE
OR CLAM STOCK.
YOU'RE GONNA
LET IT SIMMER?
A LITTLE GENTLY,
A LOW FLAME.
I'LL BRING IT
UP TO A BOIL.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
THE TOMATO BASE PART OF IT...
OKAY.
OLIVE OIL, GARLIC,
ONIONS, CARROTS,
BELL PEPPER, CHILIES...
JALAPEÑOS OR SERRANOS?
THEY'RE SERRANOS--
CELERY, PARSLEY STEMS...
LOTS OF FLAVOR.
FRESH BASIL...
A NEST OF BASIL.
A LITTLE OREGANO,
BAY LEAF, FENNEL SEED...
VERY KEY.
BLACK PEPPERCORNS.
SWEAT THAT
A LITTLE BIT.
I ALWAYS TRY AND USE,
LIKE, A REALLY GOOD WINE.
IF YOU WOULDN'T DRINK IT,
DON'T COOK WITH IT.
EXACTLY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKING ABOUT.
THIS WILL REDUCE
BY HALF.
SMELLS GREAT ALREADY.
ADD SOME FRESH TOMATO.
I'M GONNA STRAIN OUR FISH STOCK
RIGHT INTO THE CIOPPINO.
DUDE'S SERIOUS ABOUT THIS.
GIVE IT
A LITTLE STIR.
NEXT, WE'LL ADD
A LITTLE SHERRY VINEGAR,
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
TABASCO, KOSHER SALT.
MMM, BROTHER.
AND THAT'LL SIMMER
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS.
I'LL STRAIN THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE DISH TOGETHER.
12 OUNCES
OF OUR CIOPPINO BASE...
LOOK HOW DEEP AND RICH
THAT IS.
CLAMS FIRST.
LITTLENECK CLAMS....
TAKE A LITTLE BIT LONGER.
SOME DUNGENESS CRAB, MUSSELS,
SOME NICE CHUNKS OF SEA BASS,
A FEW PRAWNS RIGHT ON TOP
SO THEY DON'T OVERCOOK.
COVER THIS. SIMMER FOR
TWO OR THREE MINUTES.
JUST TILL ALL THOSE SHELLS
OPEN UP?
YEP.
OH, MY JOWLS
ARE STARTING TO SWEAT.
CRABS, MUSSELS, CLAMS,
PRAWNS ON TOP,
AND THEN THE BASS,
A LITTLE BROTH, GARLIC BREAD,
A FEW SPRINKLES OF PARSLEY,
AND WE'RE READY TO TASTE.
LOOK AT THAT
DEEP, RICH BROTH.
(growls)
(laughs)
MMM, DUDE.
WITHOUT QUESTION, THIS IS SOME
OF THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
AWESOME.
THE SEAFOOD
HAS TO BE SUPER FRESH,
AND WE'RE HERE IN CALI,
SO WE'RE ABLE TO GET THAT.
IT'S COOKED THE RIGHT WAY,
BUT THE TIME AND ENERGY YOU TOOK
TO MAKE THE BROTH
CREATES THE GREAT DEPTH.
COMPLETELY IMPRESSED.
AWESOME.
CIOPPINO.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
ONE OF THE BEST I'VE HAD.
FRESH SHRIMP, JUST ENOUGH SPICE
BUT NOT TOO HOT.
CIOPPINO'S WORKING.
I'VE HAD CIOPPINO
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
THAT ONE RIGHT THERE
HAS GOTTA BE ONE OF THE BEST.
BURGER WITH FRIES.
(woman) GREAT PEOPLE
AND GREAT FOOD,
IT JUST BRINGS
THE COMMUNITY TOGETHER.
EXACTLY WHAT
OWNERS JOHN PICKEREL...
HAVE YOU HAD
THIS ONE BEFORE?
AND HIS WIFE
MELANIE BAJAKIAN...
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
WERE GOING FOR.
A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
COULD COME TO MEET
AND COME
ON A FREQUENT BASIS.
ANY TIME OF DAY.
FRESH BERRIES
AND WAFFLE UP.
THE BREAKFAST--
MY FAVORITE, PROBABLY.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
THE HOMEMADE SAUSAGE
IS DELECTABLE.
THEY MAKE IT FRESH EVERY DAY.
IT'S AMAZING.
OKAY, BROTHER,
LET'S DO SAUSAGE.
WE GONNA START OFF
WITH A BONELESS PORK BUTT.
CUT IT IN REALLY THIN PIECES.
HOLY PIRATES OF THE CARIBBEAN
SWORD.
YOU LIKE THAT, SAMURAI?
OKAY, SO YOU'RE
GONNA MAKE THAT
JUST SO YOU CAN JUST
DROP IT RIGHT INTO THE FEEDER.
EXACTLY.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
CHILL THIS, GRIND THE SPICES?
YES, RIGHT.
KOSHER SALT, FRESHLY
GROUND PEPPER, DRIED SAGE...
LOVES PORK.
GRANULATED GARLIC...
YEP.
DRIED THYME...
T-T-THYME, ONION.
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION POWDER,
ROSEMARY, BROWN SUGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG,
CAYENNE PEPPER...
(whistles)
SOME NICE DRIED CHILIES.
THAT'S A GREAT MIX
YOU GOT, MAN.
PUT A LITTLE PLASTIC
ON IT.
AND IF I DON'T,
THEN IT ALL GOES UP HERE,
AND THEN I GOTTA
SCRAPE IT ALL OUT.
IT'S NOT HIS FIRST RODEO.
WE START ON A LOW SPEED
AND WORK OUR WAY UP.
THAT IS AWESOME.
HE'S PULVERIZED THIS
INTO A DUST
THAT'S JUST GONNA BLEND
ALL THROUGHOUT THAT PORK.
THE PORK HAS BEEN CHILLED
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
SO NOW IT'S GOT
A UNIFORM DISTRIBUTION
OF ALL OF THOSE SEASONINGS
TOGETHER.
NOW WE'LL GRIND IT
A SECOND TIME.
THIS IS LIKE
PRO PORK SAUSAGE MAKING.
GOOD FAT-TO-MEAT RATIO.
THAT'S JUST PRIME TIME.
NOW A CUP
OF ICE WATER.
ADDING MOISTURE.
IF NOT, YOU'LL COOK ALL YOUR FAT
OUT, AND YOU'D BE A LITTLE BIT
ON THE DRIER SIDE,
AND THIS'LL HOLD IT RIGHT NOW,
'CAUSE IT'S COLD,
AND THE WATER IS COLD.
ABOUT A 3-OUNCE PATTY.
GOOD-LOOKING PATTY, MAN.
NOW WE'LL GO COOK 'EM UP?
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
IN THE PAN.
LET THOSE COOK FOR A FEW
MINUTES. FLIP 'EM OVER.
IT LOOKS MONEY.
GOT SOME HOMEMADE BISCUITS
AND HOMEMADE
COUNTRY WHITE GRAVY,
HOMEMADE SAUSAGE.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM,
DELICIOUS, MAN.
THE SAUCE IS SUPER MOIST,
NOT OVERLY SEASONED.
KILLER GRAVY--
NICE AND SILKY.
THAT IS GREAT.
(woman) BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
A GREAT COUNTRY GRAVY.
THE SAUSAGE IS AMAZING.
NICE AND CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE
AND MOIST ON THE INSIDE.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
IT'S PERFECT.
YOU JUST KEEP
PUTTING IT OUT OF THE PARK.
AND OUT OF THE OVEN...
READY TO BRING IT OUT.
GOOD-LOOKING PIE.
FROM A CUSTOM-MADE PIZZA RIG...
WOW. GOTTA DIG THIS, MAN.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
AT PUTAH CREEK CAFE
IN WINTERS, CALIFORNIA...
(woman) HERE'S YOUR PAELLA.
VETERAN CHEF FRED REYES
IS COOKING...
APPLEWOOD BACON.
INSIDE...
WESTERN BURGER'S COMING UP.
AND OUT...
PIZZA COMING OUT.
WOW, GOTTA DIG THIS, MAN.
WITH A CUSTOM-MADE OVEN
FOR PIES LIKE
PROSCIUTTO AND BASIL...
VERY GOOD.
I DEFINITELY RECOMMEND IT.
CLASSIC PEPPERONI...
PEPPERONI AND CHEESE.
AND EVEN HERB-SEASONED,
FRESH ROASTED CHICKEN
FOR THIS FAN FAVORITE...
CHICKEN PIZZA COMING OUT.
THE CHICKEN'S
MOIST AND TENDER.
(woman) CHICKEN PIZZA.
THE CRUST IS THIN AND CRISPY
AND PERFECT.
AND MADE TOTALLY FROM SCRATCH.
OKAY, PIZZA DOUGH--
GIVE IT TO ME.
START OFF WITH OUR COLD WATER,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
KOSHER SALT, DRY YEAST.
WE USE A REALLY
SMALL AMOUNT OF YEAST, TOO,
BECAUSE IT'S GONNA BE
IN THERE FOR TWO DAYS,
SO WE DON'T WANT IT
TO BALLOON UP.
WITH THE COLD WATER, THE YEAST
IS NOT STARTING TO GROW.
RIGHT.
GIVE IT A REALLY GOOD MIX.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR FLOUR.
AND THEN LOCAL WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR
FROM WOODLAND, CALIFORNIA.
TURN THIS BABY ON.
IT GOES ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
IT'S PULLED AWAY
FROM THE BOWL.
GONNA PULL IT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT OUT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GO RIGHT INTO
MAKING OUR PIZZA DOUGH BALLS,
PORTIONING IT OUT TO 13 OUNCES,
PUT IT ON OUR PIZZA TRAYS.
LOOKING GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA GO
INTO THE WALK-IN.
OKAY.
THESE GUYS HAVE BEEN
IN THE WALK-IN FOR TWO DAYS.
A LITTLE MOIST
TO THE TOUCH...
WOW.
THEY'RE READY TO BE
ROLLED OUT. DUST IT.
AND YOU DO 'EM WITH
A SHEETER VERSUS BY HAND?
WE START IT OFF THIS WAY,
LIKE, ABOUT TWO OR THREE TIMES
THROUGH IT, 'CAUSE WE GO THROUGH
SO MANY, SO FAST.
AND NOW I'LL STRETCH IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
PUT A LITTLE CORNMEAL
ON MY PIE TIN.
AND NOW WE'RE READY
TO TOP IT.
OKAY.
SO PUT SOME MOZZARELLA--
WHOLE MILK--
OVEN-ROASTED CHICKEN,
NOT TOO MUCH.
NO SAUCE ON THIS.
NO SAUCE--SOME SPINACH
THAT WE ROASTED IN THE OVEN,
GARLIC CLOVES POACHED
IN A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
THEN PROVOLONE
WILL BE THE LAST TOPPING.
SHOULD'VE MADE ONE
FOR YOURSELF.
READY TO GO.
SET IT UP. I'VE SEEN
SOME BIG OVENS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE ON A TRAILER
THAT YOU TOW BEHIND A TRUCK.
THIS THING IS SMOKIN' HOT--
650 ON THE DECK.
SO YOU COME UP
IN ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
READY TO BRING IT OUT.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
REALLY GOOD-LOOKING PIE.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC OIL
AROUND THE EDGES.
SPRINKLE SOME FRESH HERBS,
SOME FRESHLY GRATED CHEESE.
OKAY.
GOOD-LOOKING CRUST.
MMM.
I LIKE THE SPINACH.
CAN'T BEAT
THE ROASTED CHICKEN.
GREAT CRUST,
DYNAMITE PIZZA OVEN.
PACKAGE DEAL, MAN.
IT'S ACROSS THE BOARD.
CONGRATS, BROTHER.
BRICK CHICKEN PIZZA.
THE CHICKEN IS A LITTLE BIT
SALTY. THE CHEESE IS FABULOUS.
PERFECTLY CRISP.
CHICKEN PIZZA COMING OUT.
COOKED JUST RIGHT
EVERY TIME.
BISCUITS AND SAUSAGE.
IT'S JUST
A REAL HOMETOWN FEEL.
CIOPPINO UP.
THEY REALLY CARE.
THEY REALLY CARE ABOUT LOCAL.
AND THEY CARE
ABOUT THE CUSTOMER.
SHRIMP AND HEIRLOOM SALAD.
THE QUALITY'S THERE.
THE FLAVOR'S THERE.
AND YOU'RE JUST GONNA
ENJOY YOUR MEAL.
OVEN-ROASTED CHICKEN UP.
YOU KNOW HOW TO COOK, MAN.
YOU GOT YOUR FINGER ON THE PULSE
ABOUT HOW TO DO IT RIGHT.
I'M IMPRESSED,
REALLY IMPRESSED.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WOW!
(growls)
(imitating cat's meow)
(imitating cat growling
and screeching)