HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
SOMEONE HAS BROKEN
THE SECURE AREA.
IT'S BREAKFAST...
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
LUNCH...
HE CAN'T MAKE
THIS SANDWICH FAST ENOUGH.
(bell dings)
(man) ORDER'S UP.
AND DINNER...
WE CALL THAT PLAYING
WITH OUR FOOD IN CALI.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
PFANNEKUCHEN
IN THE WINDOW.
A BREAKFAST SPOT STACKING
AND STUFFING
ITS PANCAKES...
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
AND TAKING CORNED BEEF HASH...
MMM.
TO THE HILT...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
IT'S--IT'S AWKWARD.
THE--THE--I'M SORRY, MAN.
IT'S OKAY, GUY.
IN TAMPA BAY,
THE MEXICAN JOINT...
(man) CHILORIO TORTA.
I'VE NEVER SEEN IT. I'VE BEEN
EATING MEXICAN FOOD ALL MY LIFE.
ROLLIN' THROUGH FLAVOR TOWN...
MMM.
THIS HAS GOT TO BE ONE OF
THE BEST TORTAS I'VE EVER HAD.
ALL RIGHT.
AND IN VIRGINIA BEACH...
FISH TACOS.
A FISH SHACK
THAT'S GOT ME SHUCKING...
I'M AN OYSTER ROCKEFELLER
JUNKIE.
FORKING...
AND PEOPLE DO THIS
AT THE TABLE?
YEP.
AND SHAKING MY HEAD.
FISH HASH--
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT ODD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
♪♪
THIS IS
A MADE-FOR-CULINARY-TV MOVIE--
HOTEL RESTAURANT VET
BEEN COOKING
SINCE HE WAS 13 YEARS OLD
RETURNS TO SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
TO OPEN THE MEGA
BREAKFAST AND LUNCH JOINT,
SERVING OVER 20,000
SCRATCH MEALS A MONTH.
THIS IS MAGNOLIA PANCAKE HAUS.
(man) BLUEBERRY PANCAKES.
THEY'RE LIKE AIR
WITH SOME BATTER.
(man) JAMBALAYA OMELET.
IT'S ALL GOOD
ALL THE TIME.
(man) BANANA'S FOSTER
PANCAKES.
FROM THE EGGS BENEDICT
TO THE HAWG & HEN,
THE MAGNOLIA SPECIAL.
YOU KNOW THIS STUFF
IS HOMEMADE.
(man) CORNED BEEF HASH.
(man) THERE IS A LOT OF
ATTENTION TO HOW IT'S COOKED.
'CAUSE OWNER ROBERT FLEMING...
OMELET MONTERREY
IN THE WINDOW.
IS RAISING THE BAR
ON BREAKFAST.
EGGS BENEDICT
IN THE WINDOW.
HIGH-QUALITY STUFF
MADE FROM SCRATCH,
EVERY SINGLE DAY,
EVERY SINGLE THING.
BACON PANCAKES.
THAT ALSO GOES FOR
HIS PRIDE AND JOY.
IT WOULD HAVE TO BE
THE CORNED BEEF HASH.
IT'S BEEN THIS LIFELONG QUEST
FOR ME.
I AM ON THE QUEST.
I MEAN,
IT'S LIKE THE HOLY GRAIL.
CORNED BEEF HASH.
ROBERT, WHAT ARE WE INTO?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME BRINE
FOR CORNED BEEF.
OH.
I'M GONNA START WITH
SOME COLD WATER, KOSHER SALT,
BROWN SUGAR,
CURE NUMBER ONE...
LITTLE PIG SALT.
HELPS PRESERVE IT,
HELPS GIVE IT A LITTLE COLOR--
CINNAMON STICK, MUSTARD SEED,
BLACK PEPPERCORN...
JUNIPER.
GINGER, WHOLE CLOVE...
ALLSPICE.
ALLSPICE BERRIES,
BAY LEAF, GARLIC CLOVE,
CELERY, CARROT...
MIREPOIX.
AND ONION.
NOW HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA SIMMER?
TEN MINUTES.
THE BIG MONSTER BRISKET.
CERTIFIED
BLACK ANGUS BRISKET.
THIS IS RIDDLED
WITH TREMENDOUS FLAVOR
BECAUSE OF THE INTEGRATION
OF THE FAT.
THE BRINE'S DONE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
SHOCK THE BRINE.
MMM.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS.
THIS IS THE PUNCH BOWL
AT THE FLAVOR TOWN
HIGH SCHOOL PROM.
WE'LL ADD OUR BRISKET
TO THE BRINE FAT SIDE UP.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
BRINE THIS, A WEEK?
UH, 14 DAYS.
WHOA. THIS SUPER SAVORY BRINE
LOCKED IN FOR 14 DAYS...
YEP.
OUT OF BOUNDS.
OKAY, SO WE'VE GOT ONE OF THESE
THAT'S BEEN BRINED.
LOOK AT THAT.
ALONG WITH AN ONION...
AND ANOTHER ONION.
PICKLING SPICE AND THEN
SOME WHOLE CLOVE GARLIC,
ABOUT A GALLON OF WATER.
FOIL ON TOP.
OVEN?
350, 4 HOURS.
SO NOW WE'RE ALL DONE.
OH.
LOOK AT THAT.
I'VE CHASED THIS FLAVOR PROFILE
MY WHOLE COOKING CAREER.
MMM! AH. OH.
WE'LL COOL IT DOWN
IN THE REFRIGERATOR OVERNIGHT
SO IT REABSORBS THOSE JUICES.
THE BRISKET'S COOLED
AND CHOPPED UP.
NOW IT GOES
TO THE BUFFALO CHOPPER?
CORRECT.
NOW WE TAKE THE GARLIC
AND THE ONIONS,
AND WE PUT THEM
IN THE ROBOT COUPE
WITH RAW ONIONS, PEPPER, SALT,
AND GARLIC, AND WE MAKE A PURéE.
WE'VE GOT THE PURéE,
THE BRISKET, AND THE POTATOES.
NOW IT COMES TOGETHER.
THIS IS A BEGINNING
OF RIGHTEOUS HASH.
START WITH SOME POTATOES,
ADD OUR GARLIC ONION PURéE.
AND THEN NOW RIDICULOUS AMOUNTS
OF CORNED BEEF.
IT GETS MIXED TOGETHER.
ARE WE GOING FLATTOP
OR SAUTé PAN?
SAUTé PAN.
YOU GONNA DO THE FLIP?
I'LL DO THE FLIP.
(whistles)
WHOO, THAT'S CRISPY.
HASH
AND YOUR FAVORITE THING.
CHICKEN IN THE POOL.
DOING THE BACKSTROKE.
MMM.
IT'S AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVOR.
IT IS THE WAY
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE DONE.
THIS IS LIKE
HEARING METALLICA ROCK
WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO
ORCHESTRA.
MMM. IT'S HARD
AND HEAVY-HITTING, BIG FLAVOR,
AND JUST SMOOTH,
COMFORTABLE UNDERLYING--
I MEAN, IT'S JUST--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
IT'S--IT'S AWKWARD.
THE--THE--I'M SORRY, MAN.
IT'S OKAY, GUY.
CORNED BEEF HASH
IN THE WINDOW.
HEAVENLY.
(Guy) HEAVENLY HASH?
SUPER CHUNKS
OF CORNED BEEF.
IT'S COOKED PERFECT.
IT KIND OF MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
MADE WITH LOVE AND PRIDE.
YEAH. AND CORNED BEEF.
(man) CHOCOLATE CHIP
PANCAKES.
THERE'S NO PLACE
I'D RATHER COME FOR BREAKFAST.
(Guy) YOU'LL FIND MAYBE TWO
OR THREE OF THESE IN A LIFETIME.
IT'S TRUE.
(Robert)
BODEGA BAY OMELET UP.
IT'S A UNIQUE APPROACH.
FROM ONE UNIQUE DUDE.
PFANNEKUCHEN
IN THE WINDOW.
I WANTED TO DO
MY OWN THING.
HAVE YOU FOUND A BREAKFAST PLACE
LIKE THIS IN YOUR TRAVELS?
NOT THAT PUTS BACON
IN WAFFLES.
BACON WAFFLE
FOR YOU, MA'AM.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE INTO?
BACON WAFFLE.
SOME BACON--APPLE CIDER SMOKE,
APPLE CIDER CURE,
60% LEAN BELLY.
THAT'S GREAT BACON.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
SOME WAFFLE BATTER.
WE'LL START WITH EGGS,
SOME WATER, SOME BUTTERMILK.
OKAY, HIT IT.
WE'LL ADD FLOUR.
THIS IS MALTED FLOUR
AND WHITE FLOUR.
AND THE MALTED BECAUSE...
IT GIVES IT
A RICHER FLAVOR,
KIND OF A SWEETNESS,
BUT IT'S NOT OVER-THE-TOP.
SALT AND SUGAR,
BICARBONATE, A LITTLE
BAKING SODA, AND SOME POWDER.
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT
WITH BUTTER.
AS WE SHOULD.
SO I'M GIVING THAT
A LITTLE WHIP.
THAT'S THICK AND DELICIOUS.
I LOVE THE SMELL.
OKAY, TIME TO FIDDLE
WITH THE GRIDDLE?
YEP, NICE AND HOT.
A GENEROUS HANDFUL
OF BACON.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS. YOU SHOULD
HAVE TO HAVE A LICENSE.
CLOSE AND A TURN.
(beeping)
ATTENTION.
ATTENTION, PLEASE.
SOMEONE HAS BROKEN
THE SECURE AREA.
SO WE'RE ALL DONE.
WOW.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. THE CRUNCH, THE SALT,
A HINT OF THE SWEET.
IT'S NICE. IT'S LIGHT.
BUT IT'S GOT GOOD CHEW.
MMM. SO PEOPLE WANT THAT COMBO.
YOU JUST FORCE IT TOGETHER.
SURE.
DUDE. THAT'S MORE WAFFLE
THAN I'VE EATEN IN 15 YEARS.
IT'S INGENIOUS.
THE SWEET AND THE SALTY--
IT PAIRS WELL TOGETHER.
THE FLUFFINESS
FOR THE WAFFLE
AND THE CRUNCHINESS
TO THE BACON.
(man) EVERYTHING ABOUT
THIS PLACE IS FRESH AND GOOD,
AND IT'S THE BEST.
MY FAVORITE PANCAKES
THAT I'VE EVER HAD.
WHEN I WANT PANCAKES,
IT'S THE ONLY PLACE TO COME.
EVEN IF THEY'RE A MOUTHFUL.
(woman) THERE YOU GO,
YOUR PFANNEKUCHEN.
APFEL PFANNEKUCHEN--I THINK
THAT'S HOW YOU PRONOUNCE IT.
PAN-A-FLOPPING.
FARFENLUGEN.
PFANNEKUCHEN.
IN ENGLISH.
IT'S A PANCAKE.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
YOU'RE DISGUISING APPLE PIE
IN A PANCAKE.
VERY DEVIOUS OF ME.
YES, YOU ARE.
MMM.
I'M SO RIPPING THIS OFF.
WELCOME BACK. WE'RE IN
SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
HANGING OUT WITH
THE PANCAKE-INATOR
AT THE MAGNOLIA PANCAKE HAUS.
HAUS.
WHERE OWNER ROBERT FLEMING...
PFANNEKUCHEN
IN THE WINDOW.
IS SNEAKING DESSERT
INTO BREAKFAST.
JUST BETWEEN YOU AND ME,
IT'S APPLE PIE, HUH?
IT'S BETTER
THAN APPLE PIE.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
I'VE EVER SEEN IT ON A MENU.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
SIGNATURE APPLE PFANNEKUCHEN.
PFANNE.
WHICH IS “PAN” IN GERMAN...
OKAY.
AND KUCHEN,
WHICH IS “CAKE.”
SO GRANNY SMITH--
MY FAVORITE APPLE.
WE PEEL THE APPLE.
ARE YOU GONNA GO FOR ONE?
YEAH, I AM.
LOOKING GOOD.
IT GOES WITH YOUR SHIRT,
I MIGHT ADD.
THE NEWEST
IN CULINARY BLING.
PUT IT ON THE HANDY-DANDY
APPLE TWIRLER.
HIGH-SPEED, NO DRAG.
YOU'LL PLAY
THE ACCORDION, PLEASE.
(as Lawrence Welk)
WELCOME TO “LAWRENCE WELK”"
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA SING A GREAT
SONG FOR YOU. HIT IT, MILDRED.
(German accent)
♪ OH, THE PFANNEKUCHEN ♪
♪ GOES IN THE PAN ♪
(normal voice) JUST DO
A QUICK LITTLE WHACK ON IT
AND OFF INTO THE PAN
IT GOES.
(normal voice)
LET'S MAKE APPLES.
BROWN SUGAR, CINNAMON,
WE'RE GONNA STIR THAT IN.
WHAT ARE WE INTO, BROTHER?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A LITTLE BATTER
FOR THE PFANNEKUCHEN--
THREE EGGS.
SOME GOOD-LOOKING YOLK.
CAGE-FREE, MAN--
WHOLE MILK, VANILLA.
WHISK IT UP.
SALT.
SUGAR, FLOUR.
GIVE IT A LITTLE MIX.
THIS IS SUPER MEGA THIN.
AND THIS COOKS UP
TO BE LIGHT AND AIRY
AND FOAMY
ABOUT LIKE THIS.
YEAH.
LET'S ROCK 'N' ROLL.
BUTTER, BIG OLD SCOOP
OF APPLES,
SPICED BROWN SUGAR, YES, BROWN
SUGAR, CINNAMON, AND NUTMEG.
OH.
THE APPLES
ARE ALL CARAMELIZED.
WE'LL PUT THE BATTER
INTO THE MIDDLE OF THE PAN.
THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS
AN APPLE PANCAKE SCRAMBLE.
PRETTY CLOSE.
HOW LONG DOES THIS TAKE?
ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
IT'S GONNA START TO PUFF UP
AROUND THE EDGES.
READY TO GO
TO THE OVEN NOW.
ALL RIGHT,
SO PFANNEKUCHEN'S DONE. SEE?
(whistles) WHOA.
WHIPPED CREAM.
YOU MAKE
THE WHIPPED CREAM YOURSELF?
YEAH, WE DO.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
POWDERED SUGAR.
DUDE. LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THE GOOEY APPLE.
MMM.
THERE'S REAL TEXTURE TO IT.
OH, YEAH.
YOU GET--GET SOMETHING
TO BITE INTO.
WHEN THAT SUGAR CARAMELIZES
ON THE BOTTOM
AND BUILDS THAT CRUST
AROUND THE EDGE,
THAT'S KILLER,
I MEAN, LIKE, REALLY KILLER.
I'M SO RIPPING THIS OFF.
ROCK STAR, MAN. ROCK STAR.
THANKS, BRO.
YOU GOT TO TRY IT.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
(woman) IT'S LIKE
APPLE HEAVEN.
(woman) CUSTARDY APPLE PIE.
THE GOOEY JUICE
REALLY BALANCES IT.
THE CINNAMON,
THE FLAVOR OF THE BUTTER.
WITH EVERYTHING ON IT,
JUST PERFECT.
(woman) IT IS AMAZING.
IF YOU WANT TO TREAT YOURSELF
TO SOMETHING REALLY GOOD,
THIS IS THE PLACE.
IT'S JUST ONE
OF THOSE RESTAURANTS
THAT YOU ALWAYS WANT TO COME
BACK TO ON A SUNDAY MORNING.
WHAT'S THE FUTURE?
YOU KNOW, ROCKIN' ALONG,
JUST KEEP DOING THE MAGNOLIA.
MAYBE THERE'S A SECOND ONE
ON THE HORIZON.
DO YOU THINK
HE SHOULD OPEN A SEQUEL?
I DEFINITELY DO.
I THINK HE NEEDS
TO GO PART DOS.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADED TO TAMPA...
WELCOME TO TACO BUS.
WHAT CAN I GET YOU?
WHERE THE TACO TRUCK
IS TAKING A BACKSEAT...
HOW BIG IS THAT SCHOOL BUS?
IT'S ABOUT 35 FEET.
AND LETTING BIG DADDY DRIVE.
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS, DUDE.
THAT SANDWICH ROCKS.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S JUST SOMETHING
ABOUT TRIPLE “D”
AND FINDING GREAT FOOD
IN UNEXPECTED PLACES,
LIKE VEHICLES.
SO HERE WE ARE
IN TAMPA, FLORIDA,
TO CHECK OUT SOME RIGHTEOUS
MEXICAN FOOD IN A SCHOOL BUS.
THIS IS TACO BUS.
WELCOME TO TACO BUS.
WHAT CAN I GET YOU?
THE BUS IS FUN.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE IN
THIS LITTLE CORNER OF MEXICO.
(man) TWO CHICHARRóN TACO.
(man) VERY AUTHENTIC
MEXICAN FOOD.
THE TACOS ARE AWESOME.
(man) TWO TACOS COMING UP.
CHICKEN BURRITO--I HAVE A LITTLE
BIT OF AN ADDICTION FOR IT.
(woman) A STEAK TOSTADA.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE FOOD.
THAT'S ONE OF THE BIGGEST
TACO TRUCKS I'VE EVER SEEN.
(laughs)
HOW BIG IS THAT SCHOOL BUS?
IT'S ABOUT 35 FEET.
BUT WHEN RENE VALENZUELA
OPENED THIS JOINT IN '91...
FIRST WE GOT CARGO VANS
AND LITTLE VANS
AND LITTLE TRAILERS.
WE NEEDED A BIGGER KITCHEN.
(Rene) ORDER UP.
SO THEY GOT A BUS...
CARNE ASADA BURRITO
COMING UP.
AND SINCE '99
RENE'S USING IT TO CRANK OUT
THE CLASSICS
HE GREW UP COOKING IN MEXICO.
(Rene) FISH TACOS.
WE WANTED TO DO FOOD THAT'S VERY
AUTHENTIC, VERY DEEP IN MEXICO.
FROM FRIED PORK RINDS
WITH SALSA VERDE...
IT'S SPICY.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
TO THE MAYAN STANDARD
COCHINITA PIBIL...
THE MEAT IS JUST TENDER
AND JUST GOES DOWN LIKE WATER.
AND THIS REGIONAL SPECIALTY
WITH PULLED PORK
AND ANCHO PEPPER SAUCE...
(Rena) CHILORIO TORTA.
I'VE NEVER SEEN IT. I'VE BEEN
EATING MEXICAN FOOD ALL MY LIFE.
TO MAKE CHILORIO,
FIRST WE'RE GONNA MAKE CARNITAS.
WE GOT A BOSTON BUTT
RIGHT HERE.
I'M GONNA TAKE
THE FAT OUT.
(Guy) OKAY, SO CUT IT
INTO SMALL PIECES.
RIGHT.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
INTO THE HOT PORK LARD.
BUILDS A LITTLE CRUST.
RIGHT. PUT SOME
MEXICAN BAY LEAVES.
ALLSPICE.
INTERESTING, I LIKE THAT.
AND ORANGE,
THERE YOU GO.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
SIMMERS,
IT'S FRYING SLOWLY.
HOW MANY HOURS?
ABOUT A COUPLE HOURS.
ALL RIGHT, SO IT'S
ALL COOLED DOWN NOW.
WE'RE GONNA SHRED IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
MMM. I LIKE THAT SPICE
WITH THE ALLSPICE IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA SHRED IT,
MAKE THE SAUCE,
AND THEN MAKE THE TORTA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOT IT.
ANCHOS--LOVE ANCHOS.
OH, YEAH.
OH. AND PASILLAS.
PASILLAS.
WE GOT A HOT GRIDDLE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM IN THERE.
OKAY.
IT'S GONNA HELP AWAKEN
THE FLAVORS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA STEEP 'EM
IN HOT WATER?
RIGHT.
OKAY, WE KEEP THE LID ON IT SO
IT KEEPS THE PEPPERS SUBMERGED.
NICE. SO WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THE SEEDS?
ARE WE JUST
OPENING THEM UP HERE?
RIGHT.
YOU CAN'T MAKE THE SAUCE
WITH THE SEEDS
AND THEN STRAIN
THE SEEDS OUT.
THEY BECOME TOO BITTER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE TAKE ALL THESE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GRIND THESE UP.
YES, FOR THE CHILORIO SAUCE.
I KNOW THIS ROUTINE.
PUT THE RED PEPPERS
IN THE BLENDER.
I'M GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF THE WATER.
OKAY.
MEXICAN OREGANO,
AS YOU KNOW, IS DIFFERENT.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE.
COMINO.
VINEGAR
AND THEN GARLIC CLOVES
AND SALT.
AFTER WE PUT IT
THROUGH THE BLENDER,
WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE SAUCE.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA FRY IT.
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF THE LARD
THAT WE COOKED THE PORK IN.
RIGHT. THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS GNARLY.
THAT'S WHAT YOU GOT TO DO
RIGHT THERE.
YOU GOT TO COOK OFF
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT BITTERNESS.
I'M GONNA PUT
THE CARNITAS ALREADY SHREDDED.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA SIT THERE
AND COOK THIS UP, LET IT COAT...
RIGHT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE TORTA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
HE CAN'T MAKE
THIS SANDWICH FAST ENOUGH.
SO THIS IS HOMEMADE BREAD.
YEAH. REFRIED BEANS
AT THE BOTTOM.
SO NOW WE PUT
THE CHILORIO ON TOP.
REFRIED BEANS ALMOST WORK
LIKE THE MAYONNAISE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, A LITTLE QUESO.
A LITTLE QUESO ON TOP,
SOME JALAPEÑOS, THEN TOMATOES,
WHITE ONIONS,
MARINATED ONIONS.
CABBAGE.
DON'T BE STINGY
WITH THE CABBAGE.
(laughs) OKAY.
AND CILANTRO.
HERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS, DUDE.
ALL RIGHT.
THE FRESHNESS OF THE BREAD
RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
THEN YOU GET THIS HOT,
LITTLE BIT SPICY OF THE MEAT.
THEN YOU GET THE CRUNCH
OF THE ONION
AND A LITTLE SNAP
FROM THE JALAPEÑO.
MMM. THIS HAS GOT TO BE ONE OF
THE BEST TORTAS I'VE EVER HAD...
ALL RIGHT.
I MEAN, ONE OF THE BEST, DUDE.
MMM. THAT SANDWICH ROCKS.
I LIKE MEXICAN PORK,
AND THIS IS THE PORKIEST PORK.
(man) THE TENDERNESS
OF THE MEAT
AND THE CRUNCHINESS
OF THE VEGETABLES IN THERE,
JUST LIKE YOU'RE IN MEXICO.
(bell dings)
TWO TACOS CHICHARRóNES SPECIAL,
RICE AND BEANS.
(man) THE TACO BUS--THERE'S
REALLY NOTHING ELSE LIKE IT.
THIS ONE WAS HERE
BEFORE FOOD TRUCKS WERE COOL.
THE NICE THING
IS WE DON'T MOVE IT AROUND.
PEOPLE CAN FIND IT.
ANYTIME, DAY OR NIGHT.
IF YOU COME HERE AT 4:00 A.M.,
YOU'RE HUNGRY.
THEY'RE ALL PART
OF TACO BUS NATION.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
HOW LATE ARE THEY OPEN?
THEY'RE OPEN 24/7.
NO.
YEAH.
FOR ME, IT'S THE HEALTHY FOOD
WAS WHAT SOLD ME.
'CAUSE THEY'RE SERVING UP
MEXICAN CLASSICS
WITH A LITTLE VEGETARIAN SPIN.
(Rene) GRILLED TOFU TACOS.
I'M HAVING THE VEGGIE BURRITO
RIGHT NOW, AND IT'S AMAZING.
MY NEW FAVORITE
IS THE BUTTERNUT SQUASH TOSTADA.
YEAH, HE'S PUTTING
BUTTERNUT SQUASH ON A TOSTADA.
(Rene) IT'S STILL MEXICAN.
IT'S NOT WELL KNOWN.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING UNIQUE
THAT BRINGS YOU TO MEXICO.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
A SQUASH.
YOU WAIT UNTIL YOU TRY IT.
IT'S FAMOUS HERE.
OKAY.
WE START
WITH BUTTERNUT SQUASH, FRESH.
I'M JUST GONNA CUT IT
INTO LARGE PIECES.
AND WHERE'S
THIS RECIPE FROM?
YUCATáN.
SO THAT'S IT? BOIL IT WITH
THE SEEDS AND EVERYTHING IN IT.
RIGHT.
DOWN IN THE WATER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
HOW LONG?
ONCE IT BOILS,
ABOUT TWO, THREE MINUTES.
IT'S GOT TO BE TENDER
BUT NOT TOO MUCH,
BECAUSE OTHERWISE IT GETS
ALL MUSHY.
DON'T WANT
TO GET IT MUSHY.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW IT'S BOILED
AND COOLED A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE SEEDS OUT?
RIGHT. WE'RE ALSO
GONNA TAKE THE SKIN OFF.
WE'RE GONNA CHOP IT UP?
RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL, ONIONS...
RED BELL PEPPER.
TOMATOES,
HABANERO PEPPERS.
(whistles)
I'M GONNA COOK THIS
A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE I ADD
THE BUTTERNUT SQUASH.
SQUASH.
NOW THE BUTTERNUT SQUASH IS
GONNA GET A LITTLE SOFTER HERE.
WE'RE GONNA
JUST COOK IT DOWN
UNTIL IT'S A LITTLE BIT
MORE TENDER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE READY?
WE'RE READY.
SO WE'RE GONNA TOP OFF
OUR TOSTADA WITH IT.
LOOKS LIKE HE'S PUTTING
A FRUIT COCKTAIL ON THERE.
TOMATOES, ONIONS,
CILANTRO, AND CHEESE.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S A LOT.
YOU CAN DO IT.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S GOT GOOD TEXTURE.
THE TOSTADA'S NICE AND CRUNCHY.
I MEAN, THE SQUASH IS
NOT FALL-APART SOFT.
THE MIXTURE OF THE RED
BELL PEPPER AND THE ONIONS
AND THAT LITTLE BIT
OF THE HABANERO
WAS REALLY DONE
THE RIGHT WAY.
I'D ORDER IT AGAIN IN
A HEARTBEAT. IT'S REALLY NICE.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
BUTTERNUT SQUASH
TOSTADA.
IT'S CRISPY, VERY LIGHT.
GREAT FLAVOR, YOU CAN'T FIND IT
A LOT OF PLACES.
(Rene) COCHINITA PIBIL.
IT'S THE BEST MEXICAN FOOD
IN WEST FLORIDA.
YOUR STEAK TACOS.
ANYBODY THAT'S INTO THIS KIND
OF FOOD KNOWS ABOUT TACO BUS?
YEAH.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
CAN I GOT
A TORTA CHILORIO?
(Guy) I CAN
GO HOME NOW, DUDE.
(laughs) WE'LL WRAP A TORTA UP
FOR A LUNCH LATER, LUNCHING.
DO ME A FAVOR, WRAP UP THE BUS
AND TAKE IT TO MY CASA.
(laughs) ALL RIGHT.
THE BOMB.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO VIRGINIA BEACH...
(man) I GOT FISH HASH UP.
FOR A ONE-OF-A-KIND
FISH DISH
THAT YOU JUST HAVE TO SEE
TO BELIEVE.
DON'T WORRY,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
I'M AS FREAKED OUT
ABOUT THIS AS YOU ARE.
I'M HERE
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
BY THE CHESAPEAKE BAY
JUST ABOUT 10 MILES AWAY
FROM THE WATER
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S SERVING UP EXACTLY
WHAT YOU'D EXPECT--
HOMEMADE, HOMEGROWN,
ORIGINAL RECIPE
CHINESE-ITALIAN FOOD
IN A TACO TRUCK.
NAH, I'M JUST KIDDING.
WHEN YOU'RE THIS CLOSE
TO THE CHESAPEAKE BAY,
YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR FRESH SEAFOOD,
AND I HEAR YOU CAN FIND IT
AT THIS JOINT--THE BEACH PUB.
(bell dings)
(man) SUSIE, ORDER'S UP.
GREAT FISH.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH.
IT TASTES LIKE
IT JUST CAME OUT OF THE OCEAN.
I GOT SHRIMP CAKES
GOING TO TABLE 9.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU GET,
IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
AND CHEF
AND CO-OWNER DAN WHELAN...
SECOND SPOT'S COMING UP
FOR FISH HASH.
HAS BEEN SCHOOLING THIS JOINT
WITH HIS FISH SKILLS
SINCE 1993.
THAT CLAM FRITTER'S
GOING TO TABLE 9, PLEASE.
THIS IS HOW EVERYTHING SHOULD
START, IS WITH CUP O' BACON.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU HAD
THE BEACH PUB?
MY WIFE'S FATHER
HAS OWNED IT FOR 35 YEARS.
I BOUGHT HALF THE RESTAURANT
17 YEARS AGO.
WHICH HALF DID YOU BUY,
BACK OR THE FRONT?
BACK HALF,
RIGHT WHERE I AM.
THIS IS YOUR SIDE.
YOU GOT IT.
I GOT A HALF DOZEN
OYSTERS ROCKEFELLER UP.
THE OYSTERS
ARE ALWAYS FRESH.
YOU CAN TASTE THE OYSTER.
YOU CAN TASTE THE SPINACH.
YOU CAN TASTE THE CHEESE.
IT'S A REALLY GOOD MIXTURE.
I'M AN OYSTER ROCKEFELLER
JUNKIE.
I HAVE TO GO TO MEETINGS
ON TUESDAYS.
IS THAT 12-STEP?
JUST 1 STEP
OF SHOVING IT IN MY MOUTH.
THE SHUCK-O-MATIC.
YOU GOT TO LIKE IT.
TAKE HER FOR A TEST DRIVE.
TAKE IT DOWN. DONE.
I CAN SEE A THUMB COMING OFF
IN THIS ANY MOMENT.
AND WHAT KIND OF OYSTER
IS THIS?
CHESAPEAKE BAY
EASTERN SHORE.
HOW MANY OF THESE DO YOU GUYS
GO THROUGH IN A WEEK?
OH, WE GO THROUGH HUNDREDS
IN A WEEKEND.
WE'VE GOT THEM
DISCONNECTED,
AND WE'LL MAKE
THE ROCKEFELLER MIX.
YOU GOT IT.
WHAT'S FIRST?
WE'VE GOT SOME WILTED BABY
SPINACH WITH GARLIC, OLIVE OIL.
OKAY.
WE'LL SLIDE THAT IN HERE.
STEMS AND ALL?
EVERYTHING. I'M GONNA TAKE AWAY
YOUR BACON. IS THAT ALL RIGHT?
YEAH. ARE YOU GONNA
PUT IT ALL ON THERE?
THE WHOLE THING.
THAT RIGHT THERE,
THAT IS SOME...
LET ME TEAR INTO THAT.
THERE YOU GO.
SEE? YOU GOT TO GET THAT
IN THERE.
WE GOT SOME
CRUMBLED FETA CHEESE...
GOOD.
SOME PECORINO ROMANO CHEESE,
AND THEN WE GOT
SOME HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM.
NOW ARE WE GONNA MIX THIS UP
AND LET IT SET UP
BEFORE WE PUT IT ON OR...
WE'RE GONNA
GO STRAIGHT TO IT.
AS SOON AS IT'S MIXED,
IT'S READY GO ON THE OYSTERS?
YEP.
AND THEN THAT
GOES IN THE BROILER.
EXACTLY.
WE'RE GONNA STEAM THESE
FOR ABOUT FOUR MINUTES,
BRING IT OUT, ADD SOME PARMESAN,
BROILER FOR ABOUT 45 SECONDS.
THEY'RE DONE. GOT YA.
(whistles)
THEY'RE ENORMOUS.
A LOT OF SPINACH, NICE LITTLE
SALTINESS OF THE BACON.
WITH YOU BEING ABLE TO GET
THE OYSTERS SO FRESH,
SHUCK 'EM RIGHT NOW,
KEEP THEM IN THEIR OWN LIQUOR,
ADD THAT MIXTURE
TO THE TOP,
THAT'S A GOOD
OYSTERS ROCK, MAN.
SERIOUSLY, THAT'S WORTH COMING
DOWN HERE JUST ON ITS OWN.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(woman)
THE OYSTERS ROCKEFELLER.
(man) THANK YOU, MA'AM.
THEY'RE COOKED TO PERFECTION. IT
JUST BRINGS OUT ALL THE FLAVOR.
(bell dings)
(Dan) I GOT CLAM FRITTERS.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS GREAT.
IT'S LIKE YOU HIT THE GOLD MINE.
AND WHEN YOU'VE BEEN
IN BUSINESS FOR 35 YEARS...
(Dan) HIT THE BELL
FOR SUSIE.
(bell dings)
YOU GET CREATIVE.
(Dan) FISH HASH
AND TWO ORDERS OF FRITTERS.
FISH HASH IS FABULOUS.
FISH HASH--
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT ODD.
(Dan) A FAMILY RECIPE, IT'S
PROBABLY CLOSE TO 80 YEARS OLD.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU CAN FIND
IN ANY OTHER RESTAURANT.
NO, IT'S SOMETHING
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT,
AND WE'LL SHOW YOU
HOW TO DO IT.
I KNOW
WE'RE SCALING SOMETHING.
RIGHT.
THAT IS A SCALING MACHINE.
IT'S COOL, ISN'T IT?
IT LOOKS LIKE WHAT I USE
TO DO MY HAIR.
IT WORKS.
NO, I DON'T DO MY HAIR
LIKE THAT.
FISH HASH--YOU SURE?
FISH HASH.
THE SPOT IS THE FISH.
YEAH, THEY GOT
A LITTLE SPOT ON 'EM.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALL IT SPOT?
THEY WEREN'T REAL CREATIVE
BACK THEN, WERE THEY?
BOY, THEY WERE REALLY LOOKING
FOR A NAME ON THAT ONE.
YOU READY? WE'RE JUST GONNA
SCALE IT REAL QUICK.
HOW MANY OF THESE
WILL YOU GO THROUGH IN A WEEK?
WE CAN GO THROUGH 100 POUNDS
OF THESE IN A WEEK.
OKAY.
AND YOU CUT HIS HEAD OFF.
YOU SAY IT SO NICELY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
CUT HIS HEAD OFF NOW.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE INCISION HERE,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF THE GUTS OUT.
IT COMES RIGHT OUT.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
YEAH, PARTY TIME.
JUST GONNA RINSE THESE OFF.
THREE TO AN ORDER.
THAT'S ALL FOR ONE ORDER?
ONE ORDER.
DID WE SEASON THIS AT ALL?
NOTHING?
NOTHING.
THAT'S THE OLD WAY
TO DO IT.
REMEMBER, OPEN MIND.
SO ONCE YOU GET IT DONE...
USE THE STEAMER.
TWO FISH HASHES IN,
JUST GIVE ME SIX MINUTES.
QUICK POP IN THE STEAMER.
IT GOES QUICK, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO,
WE'RE GONNA PICK THE FISH.
BUT YOU DON'T WANT TO EAT
THE SKIN WITH THE HASH.
YOU DON'T WANT THE BONES
WITH THE HASH.
YOU REALLY GOT
TO TAKE YOUR TIME.
WE SEND THIS OUT
TO THE TABLE FIRST
AND LET THE CUSTOMER
PICK THE MEAT OUT.
AND THEY KNOW TO DO THIS?
WELL, NOT EVERYBODY
KNOWS HOW TO DO IT.
THE HELP WILL SHOW 'EM
EXACTLY WHAT TO DO.
IT'S FAIRLY SIMPLE
ONCE YOU START DOING IT.
DON'T WORRY,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I'M AS FREAKED OUT ABOUT THIS
AS YOU ARE,
BUT I'M THE ONE
THAT'S GONNA EAT IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT'S
GONNA BECOME THE HASH PART.
YOU'LL SEE.
TAKE THE FISH,
MIX IT IN WITH THE TATERS.
THE STEAMED YUKON GOLDS.
YOU GOT IT.
A LITTLE ONIONS IN THERE.
RAW ONION.
RAW ONION, YEP.
BACON BITS.
WE'RE GONNA WORK IT TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT ALL--
AND PEOPLE DO THIS
AT THE TABLE?
YEP.
WE CALL THAT PLAYING
WITH OUR FOOD IN CALIF.
ALL RIGHT,
A LITTLE CIDER VINEGAR.
FINE GROUND PEPPER.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, IT'S ALL YOURS.
MMM. THAT'S GOOD.
THE SEAFOOD FORTIFIED WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF THE BACON FAT,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SALT,
NICE FRESH CRACKED PEPPER,
AND THE TANG OF THE ONION
AND A LITTLE BIT OF THE VINEGAR.
I LIKE THE VINEGAR ON IT.
THIS IS OLD-SCHOOL.
DEFINITELY OLD-SCHOOL.
HAVE YOU EVER SEEN IT
ON A MENU ANYWHERE ELSE?
NEVER.
FISH HASH...
NEVER SEEN IT.
ONLY AT BEACH PUB...
YOU GOT IT.
WHERE ELSE?
PICK IT UP.
I GOT FISH HASH UP.
I GOT POTATOES. I GOT FISH HASH.
THEY SEND THE FISH OUT
TO YOU.
YOU REALLY DO PICK THROUGH IT
AND MAKE THE HASH.
YES.
HOW MANY YEARS
YOU BEEN DOING THIS?
ABOUT ALL MY LIFE.
WHAT, JUST PICKING
THAT ONE FISH?
ONE FISH.
THAT'S HOW LONG IT SEEMS
LIKE IT TAKES.
(man) IT'S A GREAT
NEIGHBORHOOD ATMOSPHERE.
YOU ALWAYS FEEL WELCOME HERE.
YOU ALWAYS WANT TO COME BACK.
MAJORITY LOCALS?
EVERYBODY. THERE'S PEOPLE
WHO'VE BEEN HERE FOR YEARS.
JUST KEEP COMING IN
'CAUSE THEY LOVE IT.
YOU GOT IT.
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN.
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
PLAY IT, LAWRENCE.
(laughs)
I CAN'T HANDLE THIS.