HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ANDOUILLE.
AND DO WE LOVE THAT
OR WHAT?
SOUTHERN FLAVOR...
(woman) GUMBO.
MMM. I LIKE
THIS GUMBO, DUDE.
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
EVERYTHING THEY DO IS
JUST TAKEN UP AN EXTRA NOTCH.
THE DIVE BAR...
HERE'S YOUR SHOT.
PUTTING A TWIST...
(man) CRAB SALAD
MAYONNAISE.
ON A NEW ORLEANS CLASSIC...
(man) CRISPY
TIGER PRAWN SANDWICH.
MMM. DUDE.
IN BRADENTON, FLORIDA...
I GOT THE BOLICHE COMING UP.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
THE FOOD
IS ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
GOING ALL OUT...
(sighs) IT'S ALREADY
SMELLING AWESOME.
WITH AUTHENTIC CUBAN...
PICCADILLOS UP.
MMM. THAT IS
THE REAL DEAL.
AND IN DENVER...
PORK LOIN ORDER UP.
THE LOCAL LANDMARK...
GREAT AMERICAN
COMFORT FOOD.
SERVING UP SOUTHERN COMFORT...
MEATLOAF UP.
MMM. THE KETCHUP
PLAYS IN REALLY NICELY.
AND THEN SOME...
(woman) GINGERBREAD.
MMM. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. THANKS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
♪♪♪
SO I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S GOT
YOUR TYPICAL BAR FOOD.
I MEAN, THEY'VE GOT
POTATO SKINS,
BUT WAIT A SECOND, THEY FILL
THEIRS WITH DUCT CONFIT.
OH, AND THEN THEY'VE GOT
THE FRIED CHICKEN SANDWICH,
BUT THEN AGAIN, THEY FRY
THEIRS IN BACON FAT.
WELL, AND THEN THEY GOT
THIS LIST OF WHISKEYS,
I THINK OVER 300
DIFFERENT VARIETIES.
WAIT A SECOND. DO PLACES
LIKE THIS REALLY EXIST?
THEY DO AT THE SOUTHERN TIP
OF SAN FRANCISCO
AT THE BROKEN RECORD.
HERE ARE
YOUR SHOTS, GUYS.
IT'S LIKE A BEER AND SHOTS
KIND OF A PLACE.
(woman) CHORIZO TOAST.
IT'S A FINE DINING BAR.
THIS PLACE REALLY DOES
BRIDGE THE GAP
BETWEEN BAR FOOD...
(woman)
BEEF AND BACON BURGER.
AND HIGH-END RESTAURANT.
FROM THOSE POTATO SKINS
I WAS TALKING ABOUT...
NEVER IN MY LIFE
HAVE I HEARD
OF DUCT CONFIT POTATO SKINS
IN A BAR.
TO A TOMATO SANDWICH...
HEIRLOOM TEXAS TOAST.
IT ROCKS?
IT DOES.
AND EVERYONE'S GOT A FAVORITE.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
IT'S AMAZING.
(Guy) ALL OF THIS
IS GOING ON
IN THE BACK ROOM OF A CRAZY BAR
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
AND A BAR IS ALL IT WAS...
HERE'S YOUR SHOT.
WHEN JASON KING OPENED UP
FOUR YEARS AGO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
NOW HE'S GOT
CHEF SHANE LAVALLEY...
ON THE STOVE.
AND JAMES MOISEY...
BUTTERMILK-FRIED
CHICKEN WINGS.
ROCKING THE MENU.
(woman) CRISPY
TIGER PRAWN SANDWICH.
KILLER, INVENTIVE,
PUB FOOD,
AMERICANA, SOUL,
WHATEVER YOU WANT TO CALL IT.
I LIKE THE PIMENTO DISHES.
THEY'RE ALWAYS SUPER CREAMY.
I LOVE THE OXTAIL POLENTA.
IT'S AMAZING.
WHENEVER WE SEE ON TRIPLE “”"
SOMETHING LIKE OXTAIL POLENTA,
YOU KNOW WE GOT
TO JUMP INTO THIS.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
THIS IS ONE OXTAIL.
FROM THE BIG END
ON DOWN TO THE FLYSWATTER.
(whip cracks)
CANOLA OIL,
LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
PUT THE OXTAIL
ONTO A SHEET PAN.
AND HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
IT'S GONNA BE ABOUT 20 MINUTES
AT 500 DEGREES.
JUST TO BROWN 'EM UP
A BIT.
WE'RE GONNA START MAKING
OUR BRAISING LIQUID...
OKAY.
CANOLA OIL, WHOLE GARLIC CLOVES
AND THE CARROTS,
ADD OUR ONIONS HERE,
CELERY...
SALT.
SOME SALT IN THERE.
GIVE IT SOME TIME.
THYME GOES IN THIS?
IT'S FIGURE OF SPEECH
TIME, YES.
SPEECH.
WE GOT SOME GOOD COLOR
ON OUR VEGETABLES HERE.
RED WINE--
THIS WHOLE BOTTLE.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA REDUCE THIS
BY ABOUT HALF,
AND IT'S GONNA GIVE
OUR SAUCE A REALLY NICE BODY.
THAT'S GONNA MAKE
A NICE STOCK.
GRAB THIS OXTAIL
FROM THE OVEN HERE,
DUMP THIS
RIGHT IN THERE.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF RENDERED FAT IN THERE.
FAT'S THE FLAVOR.
LOOK AT THAT.
AWESOME.
CHICKEN STOCK.
BRING THAT UP TO A SIMMER.
LET THAT GO
FOR A FEW HOURS.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO NOW
IS WORK ON OUR POLENTA.
ARE WE GOING CREAMY
WITH THIS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
START WITH BUTTER, ONIONS,
SALT, ADD OUR CHICKEN STOCK.
BRING IT UP TO A BOIL.
OR A HEAVY SIMMER.
ADD OUR POLENTA TILL
IT COMES UP TO A GENTLE SIMMER
AND JUST STIR
EVERY NOW AND THEN.
THE HEAVY CREAM'S
GONNA GET STIRRED IN.
TIGHTENED UP
AND READY TO GO.
YEAH.
OXTAILS ARE DONE.
WE'RE GONNA PULL THE MEAT OFF OF
OUR OXTAIL BONES, RESERVE THAT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE VEGETABLES,
IN THE BLENDER.
FROM THE STOCK.
A LITTLE PURéE.
WE'RE GONNA CHECK IT
AND SEE IF NEEDS
SOME CHICKEN STOCK IN IT.
(speaking indistinctly)
LOOK AT THAT MILKSHAKE
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S A SOUP.
THAT IS SICK.
(James) TAKE SOME
OF THIS OXTAIL HERE.
COMBINE THAT
WITH OUR SAUCE.
LOOK AT THAT
OXTAIL GRAVY MADNESS.
SO I'M GONNA PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER--
CREAMY POLENTA,
RIGHT OVER THE TOP.
OH, YOU SHOULD SMELL IT.
HO, HO, HO, HO, HO.
(laughs)
JUST KIDDING.
HO, HO, SANTA CLAUS.
THIS IS MY SECRET WEAPON--
PARMESAN REGGIANO.
MELTING RIGHT IN.
I JUST WANT TO LOOK AT IT.
DONE LOOKING AT IT.
I KNOW, I SEE YOU DROOLING.
I DO THIS FOR YOU.
MMM.
DUDE, THAT'S UP THERE.
CREAMY POLENTA,
I'M TELLING YOU.
MMM. THE DEPTH
OF THE UNION SAUCE,
SILKIER THAN A GRAVY.
MMM. MMM. MMM.
YOU COULD GET LOST
IN HERE, MAN.
HOW MUCH DOES
THAT COST?
THIS IS $8.
I'M OUT OF HERE.
(laughs)
THE OXTAIL AND POLENTA--
IT'S AMAZING.
(man) EXTREMELY CREAMY
AND THE OXTAIL JUST FALLS APART
IN YOUR MOUTH.
NICE.
HEY, GUYS.
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
THEY DO A GREAT JOB
ON EVERYTHING.
(Jason) HOPE YOU'RE THIRSTY.
BUT IT WAS WHISKEY
THAT OPENED THESE DOORS.
(woman) THEY HAVE ABOUT 300
TYPES OF WHISKEY HERE,
WHICH I AM
VERY GRATEFUL FOR.
WE HAVE
A WHISKEY ON TAP.
I STARTED JUST HAVING
THEIR WHISKEY SELECTION.
THEN I CAME BACK HERE TO HAVE
SOME FOOD, AND I AM HOOKED.
CHORIZO TOAST.
EVERYTHING IS JUST TAKEN
TO THE NEXT LEVEL.
LIKE A BURGER...
(woman)
BEEF AND BACON.
WITH BACON GROUND RIGHT IN...
IT'S AMAZING.
AND BRIOCHE TOAST
TOPPED WITH DUCK EGG.
THEY'RE JUST
REALLY UNIQUE.
THEY'RE EVEN TURNING
A LOUISIANA CLASSIC...
THE PO'BOY'S AMAZING.
INTO A BROKEN RECORD ORIGINAL.
IT'S GOT PRAWNS, WITH,
LIKE, A CRISPY BATTER
AND CREAMY AVOCADO
AND SOME CRAB MAYO.
WHAT'S IT CALLED,
CRISPY TIGER PRAWN SANDWICH?
YEAH, BLACK TIGER PRAWNS--
YOU GET SIX OF THEM
IN YOUR SANDWICH.
NO WAY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR DREDGE HERE--
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
CORNMEAL, SPANISH PAPRIKA...
SOME CAYENNE.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONIONS, SALT.
COMBINE IT ALL.
NEXT STEP, I'M GONNA PEEL
AND DEVEIN OUR SHRIMP.
NOT JUST GET
THE SHELL OFF,
BUT YOU ALSO COME
THROUGH THE BACK OF IT
SO YOU CLEAN OUT
THE TRAIL.
STRAIGHT
LOW-FAT BUTTERMILK.
MM, USUALLY CHUG THAT
IN THE MORNING.
ADD SIX OF THESE BAD BOYS
RIGHT IN THERE,
JUST 15 SECONDS.
WE PICK UP A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ACID,
BUT IT COATS IT NICELY,
AND THEN THAT'LL HELP ADHERE
THAT DREDGE TO IT.
THAT IS CORRECT.
TOSS 'EM UP.
MAKE SURE THAT
YOU GET THE DREDGE
ALL THE WAY INSIDE THERE.
OKAY.
WE'RE MOVING ON
TO OUR CRAB MAYO.
CRAB WHO-O?
THIS IS A CRAB MAYO--
JUMBO LUMP BLUE CRABMEAT,
MAYONNAISE.
THAT'S ALL THE MAYO
YOU'RE PUTTING IN THAT?
JUST BINDING
ALL THIS CRABMEAT.
LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
STIR IT UP.
THAT'S THE MAYONNAISE
FOR THE SANDWICH?
OH, YEAH.
NOW WE GO TO THE SHRIMP.
WE'RE GONNA DROP THESE
RIGHT INTO THE DEEP FAT FRYER.
AT 350?
CORRECT.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
LET'S BUILD A SANDWICH--
CRAB SALAD MAYONNAISE,
SWEET GEM LETTUCE,
LIKE A BABY ROMAINE LETTUCE...
HMM.
THROW ON A LITTLE AVOCADO,
A LITTLE SALT...
THIS IS ALREADY
LOOKING RIDICULOUS.
TIGER PRAWN SHRIMP...
MMM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON,
LOUISIANA HOT SAUCE.
OH, A LITTLE HOT SAUCE
ON THIS.
CUT THIS BAD BOY
IN HALF.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
DUDE. THERE IS SO MUCH FLAVOR
IN THAT. OH, MAN. MMM.
THE SHRIMP IS BUTTERY
AND TENDER. MMM.
LUMP CRAB WITH
JUST A BIT OF MAYONNAISE.
DUDE, THIS IS CALIFORNIA FRESH
DONE THE RIGHT WAY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS, GUY.
(woman) I HAVE A CRISPY
TIGER PRAWN SANDWICH.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S GOT A REALLY NICE
CRISPY COATING,
AND THE PRAWNS
ARE REALLY TENDER.
EVERYTHING THEY DO IS
JUST TAKEN UP AN EXTRA NOTCH...
(Shane) DUCK CONFIT
POTATO SKINS.
AND IT'S INCREDIBLE.
TO FIND A BAR LIKE THIS
WITH THIS ATMOSPHERE
WITH THIS KIND
OF RESTAURANT...
(woman)
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
IS FEW AND FAR BETWEEN
IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I'M THOROUGHLY IMPRESSED.
AMAZING.
I DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE AT RIGHT NOW,
SELL THE HOUSE,
MOVE TO
THE OUTER MISSION AREA.
UP NEXT...
THIS IS OUR FAVORITE
LITTLE HANGOUT.
WE'RE HEADING
TO BRADENTON, FLORIDA...
I JUST LOVE HIS FOOD.
TO CRANK OUT CUBAN COOKING.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
IT'S NICE AND STEAMY.
STEAMY AND DREAMY.
WE'RE HERE
IN BRADENTON, FLORIDA,
ABOUT AN HOUR SOUTH OF TAMPA,
TO CHECK OUT A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S COOKING UP SOME
OF MY FAVORITE KINDS OF FOOD.
NO, NOT ITALIAN.
NO, NOT CHINESE EITHER.
AND, NO, IT'S NOT BARBECUE.
IT'S CUBAN, AND THIS IS
JOSE'S REAL CUBAN FOOD.
I GOT A ROPA VIEJA UP.
IT'S THE BEST CUBAN FOOD
IN THE UNIVERSE.
(woman) FULL CUBAN,
NO PICKLE.
CUBAN FOOD
IS A LOT OF SLOW COOKING.
EVERYTHING JUST FALLS APART AS
SOON AS YOU PUT YOUR FORK TO IT.
(man) BOLICHE,
TABLE TWO.
I'M HERE ABOUT FOUR
OR FIVE TIMES A WEEK,
ALMOST AS MUCH AS JOSE.
THAT'D BE CUBAN-BORN OWNER
JOSE BASERVA...
(Jose) ONE OF
THE TWO CUBANS UP.
WHO LEARNED DETERMINATION
FROM HIS FATHER...
MY DAD WORKED
HIS FANNY OFF.
AND COOKING SKILLS...
(Jose)
GOT BOLICHE COMING UP, OKAY.
FROM HIS MOM.
THE ENTHUSIASM
THAT JOSE HAS
JUST COMES RIGHT THROUGH
ON THE FOOD.
YOU'VE TAKEN THIS TOWN
BY STORM.
AND YOU CAME FROM
THE BACKGROUND OF...
BEFORE THIS,
I HAD AN USED CAR LOT.
YOU WERE
A USED CAR SALESMAN?
YES.
NOW HE'S TRYING HIS HAND
AT THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS...
TWO CUBANS
FOR CLAUDIO'S TABLE, PLEASE.
COOKING UP
HIS MOM'S FAMILY RECIPES.
PICCADILLO COMING.
BLUE PLATE SPECIAL
CUBAN FOOD.
WHAT ARE
WE MAKING FIRST?
WE'RE MAKING PICCADILLO,
WHICH IS ONE OF THE STAPLES
OF THE CUBAN...
LOVE PICCADILLO.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE MINE,
'CAUSE IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
OKAY, LET'S START IT.
WHAT ARE WE GOING IN WITH,
SOFRITO?
YEAH, VERY GOOD.
ONIONS, GARLIC, AND PEPPERS,
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
ALREADY IN THERE?
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME BURGER IN THERE.
80-20 GROUND BEEF?
80-20. WE'RE JUST GONNA
BROWN THIS A LITTLE BIT.
SO WE GOT RED BELL PEPPER,
GREEN BELL PEPPER,
NOT A SPICY PEPPER
NECESSARILY.
NO.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
THE SAZóN.
THIS IS THE SEASONED SALT,
LIKE IN AMERICAN FOOD.
EXACTLY.
THIS IS THE EQUIVALENT
IN LATIN FOOD.
(sighs) IT'S ALREADY
SMELLING AWESOME.
SO THE MEAT'S
ALL COOKED DOWN.
THE PEPPERS, GARLIC,
AND THE ONIONS
HAVE ALMOST DISAPPEARED.
CORRECT.
LOOK AT HOW THE MEAT'S
ALL SEPARATED.
YOU SEE THAT?
LITTLE GRANULES, NOT BIG CHUNKS.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
WHITE WINE...
NICE AMOUNT OF THAT.
DICED TOMATOES...
TOMATO SAUCE.
A LITTLE TOMATO SAUCE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE GREEN OLIVES.
OH, MY FAVORITE PART.
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF OLIVES
IN MINE, MAN.
WHAT YOU GET IS A NICE,
BRINY BITE TO THIS.
ADD THE BAY LEAVES NOW
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
WHOLE SWEET PEPPER,
WHICH IS A STAPLE
OF CUBAN SEASONINGS.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND COVER IT UP.
AND HOW LONG'S IT
GONNA GO?
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR OR SO.
TAKE THIS OFF.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
IT'S NICE AND STEAMY.
STEAMY AND DREAMY.
NOW...
SOME PARBOILED WHITE RICE.
CORRECT. DO IT LIKE THAT.
AND YOU SAID
YOU LIKED OLIVES, ABSOLUTELY.
OH.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT THERE.
GET THE PLANTAINS.
THESE ARE SUPER SWEET.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
THIS IS SOME OF MY FAVORITE FOOD
IN THE WORLD. I LOVE CUBAN FOOD.
OH, CAN YOU SMELL IT?
YOU CAN'T SMELL IT.
MMM. DUDE, THAT'S AWESOME.
MMM.
WHEN YOU'RE EATING
THE BRINY, SALTINESS
OF THIS MEAT AND THE TOMATOES
AND THE SOFRITO,
AND THEN
YOU COUNTERBALANCE IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEET PLANTAIN,
GREAT FLAVOR,
GREAT TEXTURE.
MMM. THIS IS JUST HONEST.
REAL DEAL.
EXCELLENT.
THAT IS THE REAL DEAL.
PICCADILLOS
PICK UP, PLEASE.
DELICIOUS.
(man) COOKED PERFECTLY,
REALLY FLAVORFUL,
BUT NOT TOO SPICY.
GROUND BEEF,
TOMATO, GREEN OLIVES.
(Guy) I MEAN,
THAT'S THE BOMB RIGHT THERE.
IT IS.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
I JUST LOVE HIS FOOD.
I HAVE
A TASTE OF CUBA FOR YOU.
I'VE HAD CUBAN ALL OVER
THE UNITED STATES,
AND IT IS AS AUTHENTIC
AS YOU'RE GOING TO GET.
PICK UP, LECHON ASADO.
YOU MADE A PRETTY BIG STATEMENT
WHEN YOU SAY “REAL CUBAN FOOD.”
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT MEANS THAT
YOU CAN'T CUT CORNERS.
THAT MEANS
YOU CAN'T PLAY GAMES.
CAN'T HAVE A TUNA FISH WRAP
ON THE MENU.
BUT YOU DO HAVE TO HAVE
TO HAVE A CUBAN SANDWICH...
THIS PUTS EVERY OTHER
CUBAN SANDWICH TO SHAME.
PAELLA...
INCREDIBLY FLAVORFUL.
MMM.
AND THIS CLASSIC...
I GOT THE BOLICHE
COMING UP, KATHY.
SAUSAGE STUFFED
IN A ROUND OF BEEF.
IT'S VERY, VERY GOOD.
THE NEXT ONE IS...
BOLICHE.
TAKE IT ON, MAESTRO.
WE'RE GONNA TRIM
AN EYE ROUND ROAST.
OKAY.
WE CUT IT IN HALF
LIKE THIS,
AND THEN WE GO
TO THE MIDDLE OF IT
AND MAKE A HOLE
ALMOST ALL THE WAY TO THE END.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH THAT?
OH, THAT IS FOR MY HELP.
THAT'S WHAT THEY GET AS A BONUS.
THAT'S THEIR SNACK.
OKAY.
THAT'S IT.
SO YOU TAKE
SOME RAW CHORIZO.
AND THEN WE STUFF IT
IN THERE.
STUFF IT INSIDE THERE.
NICE.
FILL IT UP.
IS THE GOAL TO NOT GO
ALL THE WAY TO THE END?
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT
IN THE PRESSURE COOKER.
IF YOU GET ALL THE WAY TO
THE END, YOU CAN'T HAVE IT CUT,
BECAUSE THEN IT'S GONNA
FALL APART.
GOT IT.
DO YOU FOLLOW
WHAT I'M SAYING?
NO, I GOT WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
OKAY, SO NOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA GET
THE SAZóN.
GOT IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA SA-SEASON.
EXACTLY.
WE'RE SA-SEASONING
WITH THE SAZóN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA COME
OVER HERE.
THIS IS THE PRESSURE COOKER
THAT WE COOK IT IN.
GET THE OIL, YOUR SOFRITO. TURN
THE HEAT DOWN JUST A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
IT'S JUST STARTING
TO GET TRANSLUCENT.
PLACE IT
RIGHT IN THERE.
OH, THIS IS GONNA BE KILLER.
BROWN BOTH SIDES?
EXACTLY. WHITE WINE IN THERE,
BEEF BROTH.
WE HAVE A DISH
CALLED ROPA VIEJA.
WE SAVE THE BEEF BROTH,
AND THEN WE USE THAT THERE.
'CAUSE THE ROPA VIEJA
DOESN'T HAVE NEARLY THE AMOUNT
OF SEASONING THAT THIS DOES.
CORRECT.
SEE?
I'M GONNA PASS THE CLASS.
DICED TOMATOES...
OKAY. BAY LEAVES.
WHOLE SWEET PEPPER.
COVER THIS UP,
BRING IT UP UNTIL IT STARTS
RELEASING THE PRESSURE...
RIGHT.
TURN IT DOWN FOR,
I WOULD SAY, AN HOUR.
(Guy) SO NOW WE'VE COOKED IT,
COOLED IT.
UH-HUH. CORRECT.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
I'M GONNA GO AHEAD AND PORTION
IT OUT, NICE, THICK CUT.
THEN WHAT WE DO IS COME OVER
HERE. WE ADD SOME SAUCE TO IT.
THAT CAME OUT
OF THE PRESSURE COOKER.
PRESSURE COOKER,
EXACTLY.
WE GO LIKE THIS.
OH, SEE, LOOK AT HOW THAT'S
JUST GONNA TEAR APART. OH.
TURN UP THE HEAT A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN WE COVER IT UP,
AND IT'LL BE
ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
OKAY.
THAT'S REAL NICE AND HEATED.
REMOVE THIS.
HERE WE GO.
I'M GONNA GET THE PLANTAINS.
MMM.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW IS THIS BLACK BEANS
OR BLACK BEAN SOUP?
BOTH.
MMM.
NOW THIS IS THE GREAT THING
ABOUT THE EYE OF THE ROUND.
SEE HOW IT'S JUST
PULLING APART? MMM.
THE SAUCE ON TOP OF IT, DUDE,
IT IS JUST PACKED WITH FLAVOR.
MMM. OOH.
AND YOU GET SOME OF THAT RICE
IN THERE, THOSE TOMATOES.
THERE'S SO MUCH FLAVOR
AND SO MUCH CONTRAST,
AND THEN THE BEANS--
THAT'S 100%...
(laughs)
MMM. AWESOME JOB.
GLAD YOU ENJOYED IT.
AWESOME JOB.
THE BEST, MAN.
(woman) AND I HAVE
A BOLICHE.
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
(man) ALWAYS SLOW-COOKED
AND THE CHORIZO GIVES YOU
A NICE SUBTLE SPICE.
IT'S JUST A VERY GENTLE,
SOFT, TASTEFUL DISH.
PAELLA'S UP.
THE FOOD
IS ABSOLUTELY FANTASTIC.
I HAVE
A PORK SANDWICH.
THIS IS OUR FAVORITE
LITTLE HANGOUT.
WELL, I GOT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING, MAN,
I'VE BEEN TO SOME FUNKY JOINTS,
TRIED SOME GREAT FOOD,
MET SOME REAL CHARACTERS,
AND THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME, MAN.
APPRECIATE IT.
MY PLEASURE. THANK YOU
FOR COMING BY. I APPRECIATE IT.
NEXT STOP...
TABLE FOUR.
WE'RE HEADING TO DENVER...
(woman) AND THE GRILLED
PORK LOIN.
I LOVE IT ALL.
TO GRAB SOME GUMBO.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
MMM. PRIME TIME.
I'M IN ONE OF THE OLDER PARTS
OF DENVER, COLORADO,
KNOWN AS THE HIGHLANDS.
NOW IT'S KIND OF
A VICTORIAN NEIGHBORHOOD.
I MEAN, THEY USED TO HAVE
STREETCARS RUNNING THROUGH HERE
AND EVERYTHING.
I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S IN A BUILDING FROM 1889
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING UP
HOMEMADE, HANDMADE COMFORT FOOD.
WELCOME TO BANG!
PORK LOIN ORDER UP.
GREAT AMERICAN
COMFORT FOOD.
(woman) TOASTED
SWEET POTATO BREAD'S READY.
IT TASTES EVEN BETTER
THAN IT SMELLS.
(woman) PEPPER SHRIMP.
EVERYTHING
IS FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S WHAT YOU CRAVE.
AND IT'S WHAT THE OWNERS CRAVED
WHEN THEY OPENED THIS JOINT...
HERE'S YOUR
BLACK BOTTOM PIE.
BROTHERS CHRIS...
THANK YOU.
AND JEFF OAKLEY...
TABLE FOUR.
AND THEIR GOOD FRIEND
CISSY OLDERMAN.
CALAMARI READY.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THE FOOD?
CLASSIC AMERICAN, LITTLE BIT
OF SOUTHERN INFLUENCE.
I JUST--
I LOVE SOUTHERN FOOD,
SO YOU SEE THAT COMING THROUGH
ON THE MENU.
LIKE PEACH COBBLER...
IT'S LIKE MY GRANDMA
USED TO MAKE IT.
OR THIS SOUTHERN STAPLE...
THE GUMBO IS JUST KILLER.
OKAY, WHAT ARE
WE INTO, CHEF?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME GUMBO.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
BY MAKING A ROUX--
STRAIGHT-UP BUTTER
AND FLOUR.
THERE YOU GO.
MAKING GUMBO, SO WE'RE GONNA
GO ON THE DARKER SIDE?
TAKE IT ALMOST
TO A CHOCOLATE LOOK
IS WHAT I'M GOING FOR.
WE'RE GONNA
BE HERE AWHILE.
OKAY, SO WHILE
THAT ROUX WORKS...
WE GET OUR GUMBO GOING.
ONIONS, CELERY, AND PEPPERS--
THE HOLY TRINITY.
LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
GONNA GIVE THAT A QUICK STIR.
BAY LEAVES.
ISN'T THIS NICE, TRAVEL
THE COUNTRY DOING TRIPLE “D”"
AND YOU GET STUCK
STIRRING ANOTHER MAN'S ROUX.
NEXT,
DICED GRILLED CHICKEN...
MMM.
ANDOUILLE...
AND DO WE LOVE THAT
OR WHAT?
OKRA,
CHICKEN STOCK.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU MAKE THE CHICKEN STOCK
YOURSELF, OF COURSE.
ABSOLUTELY.
YES, YOU DO.
SO THAT'S COOKING DOWN.
WE'LL ADD
ALL THESE SEASONINGS.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
DRIED THYME,
BASIL...
ONION POWDER,
GARLIC POWDER, PAPRIKA.
SOME FRANK'S HOT SAUCE...
CAN'T BEAT IT.
WORCESTERSHIRE,
TOMATO PASTE.
GOT TO PUT THAT IN EARLY,
COOK THAT OUT.
GIVE THIS A GOOD STIR.
WE'RE GONNA GET
SOME NICE COLOR OUT OF THAT.
ALL RIGHT, LOOK AT THAT ROUX,
PROBABLY ANOTHER 20 MINUTES.
STICK WITH IT, AND I'LL BE BACK,
AND WE'LL HELP FINISH IT OFF.
“STICK WITH IT”?
LOOKING BEAUTIFUL.
HOW'S YOUR ARM THERE? OH.
I GOT ROUX-AL
CARPAL TUNNEL.
WE'RE INTO THE GUMBO.
THAT'S GONNA ADD
SUCH DEEP, RICH FLAVOR.
FINISH OFF WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF SHRIMP, GREEN ONION.
BOY, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
READY?
I'M READY.
SOME RICE.
DON'T YOU THINK THAT BOWL'S
A LITTLE INSUFFICIENT?
WE'LL START WITH THAT.
GUMBO,
LITTLE BIT OF GREEN ONION,
BUTTER AND TOAST
SOME JALAPEÑO CORNBREAD.
OKAY, SURE WISH
YOU COULD TRY SOME.
MM.
HAVE TO GET
A LITTLE OF THAT.
MMM. THAT'S SOME
RIGHTEOUS GUMBO, DUDE.
THIS IS DEEP.
THIS IS RICH.
AND THEN YOU GET THAT ANDOUILLE
SAUSAGE THAT'S MIXED IN. MMM.
AND THE JALAPEÑO CORNBREAD--
MMM. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
PRIME TIME.
(woman) GUMBO.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE FIRE
TO IT.
JUST TAKES ME BACK
TO NEW ORLEANS.
TALK ABOUT
THE CORNBREAD.
NICE AND MOIST.
KIND OF HEARTY,
RUSTIC, HOMEMADE.
(man) GRILLED PORK LOIN.
EVERYTHING IS MADE
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
AND THEY'RE PROUD
TO SHOW IT ALL OFF.
YOU CAN STAND OUTSIDE
AND SEE EVERYBODY COOKING.
(woman) LOOK, IT'S SISSY
AND THOSE GUYS.
YOU'RE SHOWING PEOPLE
EXACTLY WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO DO MORE
THAN JUST WATCH,
YOU GOT TO GO AROUND BACK.
LIKE YOU WOULD IF YOU WERE GOING
OVER TO A FRIEND'S HOUSE.
AND YOUR FRIEND WAS
MAKING HOMEMADE KETCHUP.
FABULOUS.
YOU CAN PUT IT ON ANYTHING.
LIKE THIS COMFORT CLASSIC...
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING MEATLOAF.
IN THIS?
YEAH.
LET'S SAUTé THE VEGGIES.
OKAY.
OIL IN THE PAN,
ONION, CARROTS.
(whistles)
LOVELY.
THAT'S, LIKE, 35 "KARATS."
(laughs)
CELERY, GARLIC.
SO SWEAT THAT ALL DOWN
AND THEN...
THROW THEM ON TOP
OF THE GROUND BEEF.
80-20?
80-20.
BREADCRUMBS.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
BEATEN EGGS, SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
MIX IT UP.
DO ENOUGH TO GET IT MIXED.
GO IN THE PAN, NICE AND EVEN,
LAY THE BACON ON.
IT GIVES IT A LITTLE BIT
OF MOISTURE.
OKAY.
POP IT IN A 350-DEGREE OVEN
FOR 3 HOURS.
FANTASTIC.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
HOMEMADE KETCHUP
FOR THE MEATLOAF.
A LOT OF RAISINS
AND NOT MANY TOMATOES...
YEAH, SWEET.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
FIRST WE ADD RAISINS,
BROWN SUGAR, ONION, GARLIC,
DRIED GUAJILLO CHILIES...
GUAJILLOS ARE MY FAVORITE.
FRESH ROMAS,
SALT, PEPPER,
GROUND CLOVE,
SOME CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
COVER IT WITH SOME WATER.
AND HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO?
FOR AN HOUR.
NOW?
WE'RE GONNA BLEND IT UP.
WE BETTER HURRY UP IF
WE'RE GONNA CATCH UP (laughs).
HEY.
OKAY, READY? JUST LET IT GO
TILL IT'S NICE AND SMOOTH.
THAT'S DONE.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA STRAIN IT.
THAT'S AWESOME.
NICE AND THICK.
PUSH ALL THAT WE CAN.
THAT ALONG WITH THE MEATLOAF
IS GONNA BE A PACKAGE DEAL.
IT'S GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SLICE
THE MEATLOAF, GUY-SIZED.
KETCHUP.
OKAY.
DIG IN.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. IT'S REALLY NICE
AND TENDER, JUICY MEAT.
THE KETCHUP PLAYS IN
REALLY NICELY. MMM.
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT MEATLOAF
IN THE FLAVOR TOWN LIBRARY...
MM-HMM.
MMM. THAT'S ONE OF THE PICTURES
RIGHT THERE.
(Cissy) MEATLOAF UP.
A LITTLE SALT AND SMOKE,
IT'S EXCELLENT.
WITH THE FRESH KETCHUP,
FANTASTIC.
IT'S THE PERFECT TOUCH
TO IT.
(Cissy) AND KETCHUP
FOR THE FRENCH FRIES.
I NEVER COME TO BANG!
WITHOUT HAVING THE KETCHUP
AND FINISHING
WITH THE GINGERBREAD.
(woman)
A GINGERBREAD.
FRESH, WONDERFUL.
ALL HOMEMADE BY CISSY.
USING THE REAL GINGER,
THAT'S THE KEY.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM! HEAVEN.
AT BANG! IN DENVER, COLORADO...
(man) THE PEACH COBBLER.
OWNER CISSY OLDERMAN...
BLACK BOTTOM PIE.
IS SERVING UP DESSERT
LIKE GRANDMA USED TO MAKE.
HOMEMADE GINGERBREAD.
WHEN IS THE LAST TIME YOU HAD
SOMEBODY MAKE YOU GINGERBREAD?
(woman) GINGERBREAD.
IT'S AWESOME.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE INTO?
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
SOME GINGERBREAD.
SO LET'S SIFT FLOUR.
A.P.?
YES, ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
WE'VE GOT SALT, BAKING POWDER,
GROUND CLOVE...
(whistles)
AND SOME GROUND CINNAMON.
AND NOW WE'VE GOT
SOME SOFTENED BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA CREAM IT?
WITH THE SUGAR.
FANTASTIC.
I HAVE TO MAKE SURE
IT'S NOT ON TURBO.
GET IT GOING A LITTLE BIT,
THREE TO FOUR MINUTES.
SO THIS IS CREAMED.
YEP.
NOW WHAT?
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD MOLASSES.
OH. I LIKE THE MOLASSES.
THERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT, LET THAT GO
TILL IT'S NICE AND LIGHT.
LET ME ASK YOU
ABOUT YOUR GINGER,
I MEAN,
QUITE ENLARGED CHUNKS.
BUT IT SOFTENS UP,
AND IT GIVES IT A NICE BITE.
FRESH LEMON ZEST.
SOME EGG.
ALL RIGHT,
ONE AT A TIME...
THERE YOU GO.
LET THEM INCORPORATE.
OKAY. JUST GET THE SPATULA
DOWN IN THERE.
OKAY, SO THAT'S ALL MIXED UP.
NOW THE DRY INGREDIENTS?
WE'RE GONNA ALTERNATE
WET AND DRY.
WE'VE GOT SOME BOILING WATER
WITH SOME BAKING SODA IN IT.
REALLY?
YEAH. FIRST I'M GONNA PUT ABOUT
1/3 OF THE DRY INGREDIENTS IN.
FANTASTIC.
BOILING WATER.
OKAY.
LET IT RIP. OKAY.
WANT ME TO PUT
THE REST OF THE FLOUR IN?
YEAH. ONCE AGAIN.
IT'S SMELLING
LIKE GINGERBREAD.
BOILING WATER.
GO BIG, GO, GO, GO.
CHUG. CHUG.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK.
HE'S DOING
ALL THE WORK.
FOR SOME REASON
THIS RECIPE WORKS BEST
IF YOU MIX IT ON HIGH
FOR A COUPLE OF MINUTES.
OTHERWISE YOU GET
A FLAT CAKE.
REALLY?
MM-HMM.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GOOD.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT OUT
OF THE BOWL, PUT IT IN THE PAN,
BAKE IT FOR 1 HOUR
AT 350.
NICE.
AH.
I LOVE GINGERBREAD.
GOOD.
I'M GONNA PORTION IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE IT
WITH SOME FRESH WHIPPED CREAM.
MMM.
SPRINKLE POWDERED SUGAR,
A LITTLE PRETTY ON THE TOP.
THAT'S IT.
MMM.
THIS IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
IT'S SO LIGHT AND TENDER,
JUST LIKE WHEN YOU SAID
WHEN WE WERE MIXING IT UP.
AND THE GINGER, USING THE REAL
GINGER, THAT'S THE KEY.
MM-HMM.
SLAM DUNK. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. THANKS.
(Cissy) GINGERBREAD.
MMM! HEAVEN.
(woman) A GINGERBREAD.
IT'S NOT TOO SWEET.
IT'S SO MOIST.
LIGHT, SPICY, A PERFECT END
TO A PERFECT MEAL.
(woman) AND THE GRILLED
PORK LOIN.
I LOVE IT ALL.
(woman) GUMBO.
SOMETHING
ALWAYS SOUNDS GOOD.
(man) PEACH COBBLER.
I COULD EAT HERE
EVERY DAY OF THE WEEK.
(woman) MUSSELS.
I LIKE THE FOOD.
EVERYTHING'S GOOD.
SHORT OF MILKING THE COW
AND MAKING THE CHEESE,
YOU GUYS
ARE DOING IT.
WE DO IT ALL.
YEAH.
CONGRATULATIONS. THANKS
FOR HAVING US. BEE-BOOP.
THANK YOU.
THANKS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
(Guy) SERIOUSLY.
(Jose laughs)