HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MMM, MMM, MMM, MMM.
ANDIAMO.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD
GONE GLOBAL...
(whistles)
IN SAN ANTONIO...
ROPA VIEJA.
THE STARS AND STRIPES
PUERTO RICAN JOINT
SLAMMIN' OUT
A TRADITIONAL FAVORITE...
MMM. THERE'S NO WAY
YOU'RE NOT GONNA LOVE THIS.
IN VIRGINIA BEACH...
(woman) HERE ARE YOUR
STUFFED MEATBALLS.
AN ITALIAN BAKERY...
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
WHERE MAMA AND DAUGHTER
BOTH KNOW BEST.
WHO'S THE BOSS?
I AM.
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT COMES
TO PILING IT HIGH...
MMM.
AND STUFFING IT
TO THE MAX...
A BUNCH OF COLD CUTS
GOING INTO A STUFFED MEATBALL.
OH, THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
AND IN
BURBANK, ILLINOIS...
CHILDHOOD COMFORT
WITH AN ADULT SPIN ON IT.
A STICK-TO-YOUR-RIBS
KIND OF PLACE...
WE STARTED OUT
AS A BARBECUE PLACE
AND JUST KEPT ADDING STUFF.
GIVING A CLASSIC
YUCATáN DISH...
COCHINITA PIBIL
IN THE WINDOW.
A MODERN MAKEOVER.
IT'S PRETTY INCREDIBLE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
I'M HERE IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM FORT SAM HOUSTON
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT IS COOKING UP
ONE OF MY FAVORITE TYPES
OF FOOD--PUERTO RICAN.
I MEAN, NO MATTER WHERE I AM,
IF I HEAR THEY'RE COOKING UP
MOFANGO,
I JUST GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS EL BOHIO.
MOFANGO CON CARNE FRITA.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE FOODS
HERE.
I GOT YOUR EMPANADAS.
SPICY, TASTY FLAVOR.
MMM.
PAELLA
WITH SOME PLANTAINS.
I'M FROM PUERTO RICO. THE FOOD
HERE IS REAL AUTHENTIC.
(woman) CARNE GUISADA.
IT TASTES JUST LIKE HOME.
BECAUSE THESE ARE
THE HOME-COOKED FLAVORS
OWNER ANDRES SERBONES
GREW UP WITH...
MOFANGO ALMOST READY.
BACK IN PUERTO RICO.
WHO TAUGHT YOU
HOW TO COOK?
MY MOTHER.
MOST PUERTO RICAN MEN,
THEY DON'T WANT TO ADMIT
THAT WE COOK,
BUT WE COOK.
SO WHEN ONE OF HIS FAVORITE
PUERTO RICAN JOINTS
WENT UP FOR SALE...
MY PLANTAINS ARE READY.
HE COOKED UP A PLAN.
ROPA VIEJA PLATE.
I WANT TO KEEP THE SAME
RESTAURANT.
I KEEP THE SAME NAME.
I HAD TO KEEP THE SAME FOOD.
WHICH INCLUDED
ONE OF MY FAVORITE DISHES
MOFANGO...
IT'S ALMOST LIKE EATING DINNER
AND DESSERT AT THE SAME TIME.
MADE WITH
ANDRES' OWN GARLIC SAUCE.
THE ICING ON THE CAKE
IS THE GARLIC.
(Guy) ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A GARLIC MOJITO.
MOJITO OR MOJO?
IT IS THE SAME THING
AS THE MOJO,
BUT WE PUT IN MOJITO--
IT'S LIKE CALLING IT SMALLER.
SO THE MOJITO
IS GONNA GO IN THE PORK.
THE PORK'S GONNA GO
IN THE MOFANGO,
AND THE MOFANGO
IS GONNA GO IN MY MOUTH.
THAT'S CORRECT.
(whistles)
THAT'S THE PROCESS.
PUT THE GARLIC
THAT WE ROASTED ALREADY.
WE ADD OLIVE OIL,
SAZóN.
GOTTA THINK OF THIS AS, LIKE,
PUERTO RICAN SEASONED SALT.
MM-HMM.
ACHIOTE.
TO USE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE RED COLOR.
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA BLEND.
OKAY, ARE WE GOOD?
YOU WANT TO TASTE IT?
OH, A LITTLE BIT OF THE SALT
AND THE GARLIC,
THAT BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE MARINADE
FOR THE PORK BUTT.
OREGANO, ADOBO,
A LITTLE BIT OF SAZóN,
THE FAMOUS CILANTRO...
(whistles)
AND PEPPER.
REMEMBER THAT MOJITO?
THE SMALL MOJO.
GREEN PEPPER, YELLOW PEPPER,
AND THEN RED PEPPER.
I'M GONNA BAPTIZE IT.
BAPTIZE IT?
YEAH.
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OIL.
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN THE BLENDER.
WHAT KIND OF MEAT
ARE WE GONNA MARINATE?
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
PORK BUTT.
WE TRIM THE FAT,
CUT IT IN PIECES,
AND THEN MARINATE IT.
AND DON'T BE SHY.
A LOT OF THIS. THERE WE GO.
AND HOW LONG
ARE WE GONNA LET IT MARINATE?
AT LEAST TWO HOURS.
GOT IT.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE PART.
I'M A BIG FAN
OF MOFANGO.
SO A GREEN PLANTAIN.
WE CUT THE END.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
CUT ON THE CORNERS.
USE A LITTLE SPOON.
DO YOU SEE HOW EASY?
YEAH, I LIKE
YOUR LITTLE SPOON IDEA.
(laughs)
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
ALL THE PEELS OFF OF IT.
UH-HUH.
CUT IT,
AND THEN WE FRY IT.
YES, SIR.
WE'VE GOT
THE COOKED-DOWN PLANTAINS.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT IN A PILóN.
FIRST THING,
YOU PUT THE MOJO DE AJO.
THAT'S THE MOJITO.
YEAH, MOJITO.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA
PUT THE PLANTAINS IN IT,
AND NOW
WE'RE GONNA SMASH IT...
I GET IT.
TO MAKE KIND OF LIKE
A LITTLE PASTE. ALMOST DONE.
HOW ARE WE LOOKING?
YEAH, IT LOOKS GOOD.
SEE?
CHECK THAT OUT.
WHEN DOES A BUNCH OF MASHED THAT
IN A WOODEN BOWL
LOOK LIKE IT'S GONNA BE GOOD?
WAIT TILL YOU TRY THIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE ADOBO AND MOJITO.
AND WE'RE GONNA SMASH MORE.
THERE WE GO.
NOW WE'RE GONNA REMOVE
THE MOFANGO FROM THE PILóN.
JUST SEPARATE IT.
AND HERE YOU GOT
YOUR MOFANGO.
PUT IT ON THE PLATE.
MORE GARLIC.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FRY THE PORK.
PUERTO RICO FRY IS BETTER.
EVERYTHING.
OKAY, SO WE'VE GOT
THE PLANTAINS
AND THE FRIED PORK.
FRESH ONION AND MOJITO.
AND HERE YOU GO.
OH, MY GOSH. MMM.
REALLY GOOD.
TASTE NOTHING LIKE A BANANA.
MMM.
THINK ABOUT REALLY SUPER
FLAVORFUL MASHED POTATOES,
GOOD GARLIC TO 'EM
BUT GREAT TEXTURE.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SWEET,
BUT THEN YOU GET THE GARLIC
AND THE SEASONING, MMM.
YOU'RE ROCKIN'
ON THE GARLIC, DUDE.
NICE LITTLE MARINADE BUT YOU
CAN STILL TASTE THE PORK.
MMM, THAT'S IN THE TANK
THAT FUELS THE BUS
THAT GOES TO FLAVOR TOWN.
THERE'S NOW WAY YOU'RE NOT
GONNA LOVE THIS, I SWEAR.
MOFANGO CON CARNE FRITA.
MOFANGO.
THIS IS WHAT
I COME HERE FOR.
IT'S AMAZING.
SOFT AND SUCCULENT
AND FULL OF FLAVOR.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY THEY BUILT
THAT MILITARY BASE SO CLOSE
TO YOUR RESTAURANT.
70% OF MY BUSINESS
CAME FROM THE MILITARY.
AND AS AN ARMY VETERAN HIMSELF,
ANDRES MAKES A POINT
TO SUPPORT THOSE WHO SERVE.
THEY DEFINITELY CATER
TO THE MILITARY COMMUNITY.
GOOD FOOD AT LOW PRICE--
THAT'S BASICALLY IT.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
THEY'VE GOT HUGE PLATES
OF LATIN COMFORT FOOD
FROM PUERTO RICAN STEW...
(woman) CARNE GUISADA.
JUST GREAT FLAVORS.
TO A HAM, PORK,
AND BEEF SANDWICH
I LOVE IT.
AND EVEN THIS LATIN CLASSIC...
(woman) ROPA VIEJA.
THANK YOU.
ENJOY.
AND WE'RE GONNA DO
ROPA VIEJA.
SO A NICE BIG BRISKET.
THE FIRST THING
YOU NEED TO DO,
YOU NEED TO CUT IT
IN FOUR PIECES.
SO IT CAN BREAK DOWN.
WE GOT BOILING WATER,
SALT, PEPPER,
BAY LEAF,
ABOUT FIVE GARLIC CLOVES.
DON'T BE SHY.
I GOTTA TELL YA,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ABOUT THIS WHOLE EXPERIENCE
IS YOUR ACCENT. BEAUTIFUL.
OH.
VINEGAR.
SO WE LET THAT ALL
SIT THERE IN THE BOIL.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH THE BRISKET.
AND HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA BOIL?
IT'S GONNA BOIL
FOR FOUR HOURS.
FOUR HOURS UNTIL
IT'S FORK-TENDER.
FOUR HOURS.
SO WE LET THIS GO
THEN WE SHRED IT.
WE MAKE THE ROPA VIEJA.
YES, SIR.
OKAY.
LET'S LET IT COOL. NOW WE'RE
GONNA SHRED THE BRISKET.
WE'RE GONNA HEAT THIS UP,
PUT A LITTLE CRISP ON IT.
MM-HMM.
AND THEN
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
YES, SIR.
BROTH FROM THE BOILING BRISKET
FOR FLAVOR.
OKAY, A LITTLE BIT
OF MOISTURE IN THERE.
SAZóN...
TRICOLOR BELLS...
ONIONS AND OLIVES.
PIMENTóN.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER,
ADOBO, CILANTRO.
OKAY, SO WE LET THIS COOK DOWN
FOR WHAT, 30, 40 MINUTES?
30, 40 MINUTES.
OKAY. LOOK AT THAT.
GOTTA GET THAT JUICE
IN THERE, TOO.
THERE YOU GO.
RIGHT THERE--
ROPA VIEJA.
MMM. GOOD.
MMM.
GET A STRONG BEEF FLAVOR.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT OLIVE IN THERE. MMM.
SOME TWICE-FRIED GREEN PLANTAIN,
THE TOSTONES, MMM.
TONS OF GREAT FLAVOR,
REALLY TENDER.
MMM. DYNAMITE.
(woman) ROPA VIEJA.
IT IS SO GOOD.
IT TASTES LIKE I'M ON VACATION.
ROPA VIEJA COMING OUT.
THE BOMB.
IT SPOKE TO ME...
IT SPOKE TO YOU.
IN A LANGUAGE
THAT I DIDN'T UNDERSTAND.
LOVE IT, LOVE IT, LOVE IT.
GREAT JOB, MAN. LOVE THE PLACE.
CONGRATULATIONS.
ALL RIGHT.
COMING UP...
NAPOLETANA, TABLE 1.
WE'RE HEADED
TO VIRGINIA BEACH...
THEY DO IT
JUST LIKE ITALY.
WHERE A MOM-AND-DAUGHTER
SHOP...
BUT NOW YOU PLAY THE FOCACCIA
PIANO. ♪ DA DA DON ♪
IS SERVIN' UP
AUTHENTIC ITALIAN...
THAT'S A RIDICULOUS SIZE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
WITH A SIDE OF ATTITUDE.
I'M TELLING YA,
I'M ON THE VERGE OF GETTING
KICKED OUT OF THIS KITCHEN.
I'M IN THE SANBRIDGE AREA
OF VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
LOOKING FOR A TRIPLE "D" JOINT.
I MEAN, I HIT ALL KINDS.
IT DOESN'T MATTER THE TIME,
THE PLACE, OR THE TOWN.
AND MY HUNT LEADS ME HERE
WHERE I HEAR
A MOTHER-AND-DAUGHTER TEAM
ARE KNOCKING OUT THE REAL-DEAL
ITALIAN AT THIS JOINT--
RIGOLETTO
ITALIAN BAKERY AND CAFé.
THEY DO IT
JUST LIKE ITALY.
CHICKEN VENICE TABLE 4.
THE BREADS ARE FRESH.
THE MEATS ARE FRESH.
EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE.
HOW MANY TIMES
HAVE YOU BEEN TO THIS PLACE?
I CAN'T COUNT.
YOU DON'T NEED TO BE GOOD
AT MATH TO KNOW THIS.
THE NAPLES BACKGROUND
THESE LADIES SHARE
EQUALS REAL-DEAL ITALIAN.
NAPOLETANA, TABLE 1.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
THAT I FOUND HERE
THAT HAS HOMEMADE LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
BAKED ZITI, ORDER UP.
(bell dings)
IN THIS CORNER,
GILDA DI DOMENICO,
IN THE OTHER,
DAUGHTER, JESSIE GOSHA.
THEY'VE BEEN GOING TOE-TO-TOE
AT THIS PLACE SINCE 2006.
WATCH THIS.
WHO'S THE BOSS?
I AM.
I AM. NO, I AM.
I AM. I AM.
WHO'S THE BETTER COOK?
I AM.
HOW DO YOU
GET ANYTHING DONE?
WE ALWAYS GET IT DONE.
NO MATTER WHAT.
IT KIND OF SEEMS LIKE TWO TRAINS
GOING ON THE SAME TRACK.
THAT'S WHY IT WORKS.
THIS TRAIN ROLLS THROUGH
A ROCKIN' MENU
OF ITALIAN FAVORITES,
AND A BUNCH OF 'EM START
WITH SOME KILLER FOCCACIA.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE FOCACCIA
FOR OUR PANINI.
AND HOW MANY FOCACCIA
DO YOU MAKE A DAY?
I MAKE 14.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
OKAY, WE NEED
SOME WARM WATER,
YEAST, SUGAR, ACTIVATE IT,
LET IT SET,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
AND THEN WE START TO MIX.
OKAY, WE'RE ON 1?
ON 1.
FIRE IN THE HOLE.
SO WE RUN IT ON SLOW RIGHT NOW,
BECAUSE IF IT WAS ON HIGH,
WITH HER THROWING
THAT FLOUR...
WE NEED
SOME MORE WATER.
YES, MA'AM.
YOU KEEP RUNNING AWAY.
I THOUGHT
YOU WERE DANGEROUS.
YOU FEEL
THREATENED BY ME?
NO, I'M NOT THREATENED
BY YOU.
I JUST DON'T
WANT TO GO AROUND
LOOKING LIKE STAY PUFT
THE MARSHMALLOW MAN.
WHY NOT?
I'M ON THE VERGE OF GETTING
KICKED OUT OF THIS KITCHEN.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU DO
BESIDES COOK?
I DANCE.
DANCE.
OKAY, SO IT'S DONE.
YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT THIS IS?
THIS IS THE BLANKET
FROM ALITALIA.
ALL RIGHT, LOOK AT THAT.
BEAUTIFUL.
GONNA STRETCH THIS OUT.
IT'S GONNA STRETCH IN MY PAN.
I'M NOT GONNA DO IT.
OH.
I DON'T KNOW WHY
I STARTED CATCHING ON
THIS ITALIAN ACCENT
ALL OF THE SUDDEN.
I STARTED HANGING OUT--
I'M NOT GONNA TOUCH IT.
(speaking Italian)
SHE PROBABLY JUST SAID,
"YOU LOOK LIKE A DOG."
OKAY, ANDIAMO.
NOW ARE WE GONNA LET THIS
PROOF AGAIN IN THE PAN?
JUST RELAX A LITTLE.
YEAH.
SO THEN WE--
AND WE'LL PULL IT ONE MORE TIME.
WE'LL FILL
THE FOUR CORNERS.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA SEASON THIS WITH?
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
MY SPECIAL SEASONING,
AND I'M GONNA SPRINKLE IT
FRESH ROSEMARY FROM MY YARD.
I'M GONNA MASSAGE THE SPICES
INTO THE DOUGH WITH MY FINGERS.
PUT YOUR FINGERS IN.
NOW YOU PLAY
THE FOCACCIA PIANO.
♪ DA DA DON ♪
MASSAGE.
LIKE A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN'S BACK,
YOU JUST MASSAGE IT.
LISTEN, IF I SEE ANY OF THIS
ON A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN'S BACK,
I'M OUT.
OVEN IS ON
AT 350.
350.
WE'RE JUST GONNA PUT IT IN
FOR 22 MINUTES.
NOT 21.
22.
NOT 23.
I AM ON ITALIAN TIME.
BEAUTIFUL. MWAH.
LOOK AT THAT. SEE THAT STEAM
COMING OFF OF THAT?
MMM. I LIKE THAT
GARLIC SALT ON TOP.
NICE CRUST.
IT'S CHEWY AND DENSE.
NOT REALLY HEAVY.
MMM. GOOD TEXTURE.
THIN TEXTURE.
NOT TOO MUCH TOPPING.
NO, YOU DON'T WANT TO.
OTHERWISE, YOU LOSE ALL
THE FLAVOR OF THE BREAD.
AND THE BREAD'S GOT GREAT
FLAVOR AND A NICE CRUST.
I LOVE THE BREAD.
I ESPECIALLY LIKE THE FOCACCIA.
I JUST LOVE IT ALL.
THE BAKING OPENED THE JOINT,
AND DESSERTS CAME FIRST.
I'M EATING A CANNOLI TODAY,
AND IT'S GREAT.
NOW I'M ABOUT TO KILL MY SON,
BECAUSE HE'S EATING AN éCLAIR,
AND HE WON'T SHARE WITH ME.
(laughs)
AFTER CHURCH ON SUNDAYS,
I COME IN AND GET CANNOLIS.
THEY DON'T LAST.
NEITHER DO THE SANDWICHES,
LIKE THE NAPOLETANA
WITH EGGPLANT AND PROSCIUTTO,
THE VESUVIO PILED HIGH
WITH CAPICOLA AND SALAMI,
OR THEIR TOP SELLER...
(woman) HERE'S YOUR
FLORINTINA ON FOCACCIA.
IT'S LIKE A GOURMET
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
OKAY, SO WHAT
ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING THE FLORINTINA--
OUR SHAVED STEAK.
GET IT GOING.
I GOT THE TONGS.
ALL RIGHT.
I SLICE THE RIB EYE
INTO THIN STRIPS.
JUST THINK
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK MEAT.
NOW WE DO
SALT AND PEPPER...
OKAY.
FRESH CUT PARSLEY,
AND THEN SIX CLOVES
OF FRESH CRUSHED GARLIC,
OLIVE OIL, EXTRA VIRGIN,
AND THE MEAT MARINATES.
LET IT MARINATE.
YOU ALMOST GOT STEAK TARTARE
RIGHT THERE.
SO WE LET THIS COOL OVERNIGHT,
AND THEN WE'LL COOK IT UP.
ALL RIGHT.
OLIVE OIL,
NOT TOO MUCH,
A LITTLE BIT
OF STEAK.
OH, NICE PORTION
OF THAT.
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT A NICE
LITTLE PAN-FRY ON THAT? MMM.
SOMETHING ABOUT HAVING
THAT SALT IN ALL THAT MIXTURE
GETTING A LITTLE MARINADE
KIND OF DOESN'T DRY THE MEAT OUT
BUT PULLS OUT SOME OF
THE MOISTURE, AM I CORRECT?
YES, PERFECT.
PEPPER, SALT,
GARLIC, A LITTLE MORE.
YEAH, DON'T BE SHY
WITH THAT.
THE KIDS, NOT SO MUCH.
SEE HOW IT STARTS TO CRUST UP
THERE A LITTLE BIT?
YOU GOTTA LEAVE IT ALONE,
THOUGH, AND LET IT...
YEAH, YOU GOTTA LET IT
BUILD THE CRUST.
DON'T TOUCH IT TOO MUCH.
IF YOU MESS WITH IT TOO MUCH,
IT DOESN'T GET THE CRUST.
THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
WHAT ABOUT
NO MESSING WITH IT?
NOW YOU GOTTA
MESS WITH IT.
LET ALL OF 'EM GET MARRIED
AND LOVE EACH OTHER,
GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
YOU MAKE 'EM GET MARRIED
AND LOVE EACH OTHER
BY JAMMING A RUBBER SPATULA
INTO 'EM?
IN BETWEEN 'EM
AND THEN PUSHING 'EM
ALL TOGETHER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA LET IT
BUILD CRUST AGAIN?
NOW IT'S GONNA
GET BEAUTIFUL.
MMM.
NOW THEY'RE ALL
MARRIED AND HAPPY.
THEY'RE GONNA
GET A LITTLE DRUNK.
NECESSARY.
ALWAYS.
A LITTLE MORE
MARSALA WINE.
YEAH.
MMM.
PROVOLONE CHEESE, FIVE SLICES,
NICE AND THICK.
YOU'LL HAVE ENERGY
AFTER THIS.
FIVE PIECES OF PROVOLONE.
THAT'S, LIKE,
1/2 A POUND OF PROVOLONE
THAT YOU JUST PUT IN THERE,
AND THAT BREAD'S
JUST GONNA SOAK UP
ALL THAT RENDERED DOWN FAT.
THE MARSALA,
THE OLIVE OIL.
ROLLING THE MEAT UP
ON TOP OF THE CHEESE.
SO THERE'S CHEESE IN THE CENTER
OF THESE MEAT-CAPADE.
WE'RE GONNA POUR THE JUICE
ON IT NOW. THERE WE GO.
OH, THAT'S
A RIDICULOUS SIZE.
NO, IT'S NOT.
THE SECRET, COLD TOMATOES.
COLD TOMATOES.
IT GIVES IT
A LITTLE BREAK.
DO YOU WANT ME TO CUT IT
IN HALF? YOU CAN'T HANDLE IT?
CAN'T HANDLE IT?
PLEASE CUT IT IN HALF.
JUST OLD LADIES ASK US
TO CUT IT IN HALF.
THAT'S WHY I WAS ASKING.
I WAS DOING IT
SO I COULD SHARE IT WITH YOU.
LOOK AT THIS, LOOK AT ALL
THE JUICE INSIDE OF THAT
AND THE TON OF PROVOLONE.
MMM, IT'S RICH.
MMM, IT'S JUICY.
IT'S ENORMOUS.
MMM, IT'S CREAMY.
MMM, ALL THAT CHEESE--
REALLY GOOD PROVOLONE, TOO.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
COMING OUT OF THAT PROVOLONE.
AND YOU GET
A TON OF MEAT.
I MEAN, I'M LITERALLY FOUR
OR FIVE BITES INTO THIS,
AND I'M PULLING INTO THE DEPOT
IN FLAVOR TOWN OF FULL.
THAT'S ITALIAN CHEESESTEAK
RIGHT THERE, BABY.
OH, THAT WAS GOOD.
I'M NOT KIDDIN' YA.
THAT MEAT IS JUST--MMM.
MMM-MM-MMM.
BUT THIS ISN'T JUST
A SANDWICH PLACE
WHEN WE COME BACK.
HA HA!
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
STUFFED MEATBALLS.
IT'S ON THE LOW-FAT MENU.
YEAH, EAT THIS.
IT'LL MAKE YOU LOW AND FAT.
(laughs)
TRIPLE "D" IS AT RIGOLETTO'S
ITALIAN BAKERY AND CAFé
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA.
IS IT BIG ENOUGH?
IT'S HUGE.
DUDE, IT'S RIDICULOUS.
MOTHER GILDA AND DAUGHTER
JESSIE ARE THE BOSSES,
THE COOKS, AND DEFINITELY
THE HEART OF THIS PLACE.
(man) YOU COME IN HERE.
YOU'RE MADE TO FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE ONE OF THE FAMILY.
WE'RE MORE LIKE
AN ITALIAN HOME, YOU KNOW?
PEOPLE COME IN.
WE KNOW THEIR FIRST NAME.
WE KNOW WHAT THEY DRINK.
WE KNOW WHAT THEY EAT.
STUFFED MEATBALLS.
YES, SIR.
MMM, DUDE,
I'D WEIGH 5,000 POUNDS
IF I LIVED WITHIN 500 MILES
OF THIS PLACE.
ALL RIGHT
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
STUFFED MEATBALLS.
STUFFED WITH WHAT?
MOZZARELLA...
MOZZARELLA.
AND A LOT MORE
THAN THAT.
MORE THAN MOZZARELLA?
A LOT MORE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE MAKING
THE STUFFING THAT GOES INSIDE.
MAKE IT QUICK, BECAUSE I'M
GONNA BE--INSIDE OF WHAT?
YOU, IN A MINUTE.
HA HA!
REALLY, A STUFFED MEATBALL?
YEAH.
A BUNCH OF COLD CUTS
GOING INTO A STUFFED MEATBALL.
MEATBALL.
FIRST STEP
IS TO DICE AND SLICE
GENOA SALAMI,
SPICY CAPICOLA...
SPICY CAPICOLA.
BLACK FOREST HAM...
BLACK FOREST HAM.
PROVOLONE...
A LITTLE PROVO.
AND MOZZARELLA.
A LITTLE MOZZ, CORRECT?
YOU GOT IT.
OH, THERE'S NOTHING
WRONG WITH THAT.
IT'S ON
THE LOW-FAT MENU.
YEAH, EAT THIS.
IT'LL MAKE YOU LOW AND FAT.
(laughs)
IT'S MIXED. WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A MEATBALL FIRST.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT INSIDE. WORD.
YOU'VE GOT EVERYTHING HERE
EXCEPT NO MILK.
NO MILK. I DON'T DO MILK.
THEY'RE NOT WIMPY.
OKAY.
WE CAN'T HAVE
WIMPY MEATBALLS.
WIMPY?
I JUST HAD SOME
DENTAL WORK DONE.
I DON'T WANT TO GO BREAKING
ANYTHING BY EATING...
TRUST ME.
THESE HARD MEATBALLS.
TRUST ME, THE STUFF INSIDE
IS GONNA MAKE IT WONDERFUL.
YOU PUT THOSE ON
LIKE YOU'RE A DOCTOR.
DOCTOR OF
MEATBALL MAKING.
OKAY, WHAT DO YOU GOT?
NOW I'M PUTTING
IN A LEANER MEAT
MIXED TOGETHER
WITH A FATTIER MEAT,
22 EGGS...
NOT 23.
22 IS PERFECT.
THAT'S A LOT
OF EGGS.
I KNOW.
WE WANT IT A LITTLE MOIST.
BECAUSE THESE BREADCRUMBS
ARE GONNA SOAK UP
EVERY BIT OF MOISTURE
THAT THESE THINGS HAVE.
BUT THAT'S
WHAT WE WANT.
WE WANT DENSE MEATBALLS
SO NOTHING COMES OUT.
YOU WANT TO DO IT?
DO YOU KNOW HOW TO DO IT?
WHAT ARE THESE CALLED,
THE DESERT MEATBALLS?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE GIVE YOU THE MEATBALLS
FREE HERE AND THEN, GUY,
YOU HAVE TO PAY 20 BUCKS
FOR A GLASS OF WATER.
LET'S SEE IF YOU SAY THAT
AFTER YOU EAT IT.
DRIED PARSLEY...
PECORINO ROMANO,
PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
SURE.
GARLIC POWDER,
SALT, AND PEPPER.
AND NOW I'M MIXING.
OKAY, SO NOW
BRING OVER THE FILLING.
ALL RIGHT, YEP.
THE SCOOPER-DOOPER
AND A PAN THAT COLUMBUS
BROUGHT WITH HIM ON THE PINTA.
SANTA MARIA.
I'M GONNA SCOOP
THE MEATBALL MIXTURE,
PLACE IT INTO MY HAND,
MAKE A HOLE IN IT,
TAKE A PINCH OF STUFFING,
STUFF IT IN, AND CLOSE IT UP.
I DO THIS, EACH MEATBALL,
ONE AT A TIME, ALL DAY LONG.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE MAKE THESE UP.
YES.
IS THE OVEN 350?
YEP.
325.
320--HEY.
YOU BURN THE MEATBALL
AT 350.
IT BURNS THE MEATBALL,
PUTS THE LOTION ON.
LOW AND SLOW.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
DO THE SPAGHETTI. DON'T.
IT'S COLD.
DON'T. IT'S NOT GONNA BE COLD
IN A MINUTE.
AH, AH.
IT'S COLD.
NOT YET. AH.
YOU CAN'T PUT THE COLD
SPAGHETTI IN THE--
YES, YOU CAN.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE MY GRANDMA'S SAUCE
IS GOING ON IT,
AND THAT MAKES EVERYTHING
ALL BETTER.
OUR CRUSHED TOMATOES...
OKAY.
WE GOT A LITTLE ROOM BACK THERE,
AND MY GRANDMA SITS IN THERE,
AND SHE MAKES
THE TOMATOES.
IT TASTES BETTER WHEN MY GRANDMA
DOES IT WITH HER HANDS.
OKAY, SO THE HOT MEATBALLS
STUFFED WITH
THE ENTIRE DELI SELECTION...
MINUS WHAT YOU ATE.
OH, NICE.
ALL RIGHT, TWO MEATBALLS,
SPAGHETTI, NICE AND FRESH,
AL DENTE.
BEAUTIFUL.
WE'RE NOT DONE YET.
OF COURSE,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
TO PUT MORE SAUCE ON IT.
GRANDMA'S GONNA BE
SMASHING A LOT OF TOMATOES.
SHE DOES ALL RIGHT.
PERMISSION
TO PICK UP THE FORK.
ABSOLUTELY, SIR.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT ALL THAT CREAMINESS
FROM THE PROVOLONE AND THE MOZZ.
MMM, BECAUSE THE INSIDE
IS SO CREAMY,
MMM, YOU DO NEED
THAT HARD EXTERIOR
ALMOST TO KEEP IT
LOCKED IN.
YEAH.
MMM.
NOT OVERLY FLAVORED.
YOU KNOW, I WAS WONDERING WITH
ALL THOSE COLD CUTS IN THERE
IF THERE WAS GONNA BE TOO MUCH
SALT--A REALLY NICE BALANCE.
A LITTLE SWEETNESS
COMING OUT OF THAT HAM,
A LITTLE OUT OF THE MOZZ.
YEAH.
A LITTLE SALT
FROM THE PROVOLONE, MMM.
PASTA IS AL DENTE,
THE SAUCE IS SWEET,
AND JUST LUSCIOUS AND GREAT
TOMATO FLAVOR.
THE FRESH BASIL
REALLY SINGS OUT.
I MEAN, IT'S DYNAMITE.
HERE ARE YOUR
STUFFED MEATBALLS.
OH, THANK YOU.
A COMBINATION OF A LITTLE BIT
OF DELI MEATS AND SPICES.
I'M NOT A KITCHEN MAN,
BUT EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
IT TASTES GOOD TO ME.
THE FOOD, TO ME, IT'S A LOT
LIKE THE FOOD I GREW UP WITH,
SO IT'S ALMOST
LIKE COMING HOME.
LADIES, CONGRATULATIONS.
VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU, GUY.
FOOD'S DYNAMITE.
YOU'RE WONDERFUL.
AND THE STORIES
ARE EVEN FUNNIER.
NOW LET ME JUST ASK YOU
ONE MORE TIME. WHO'S THE BOSS?
I AM.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO BURBANK, ILLINOIS...
FULL SLAB OF RIBS
GOING IN THE WINDOW.
WHERE SOUTHERN COMFORT...
THE FLAVOR, THE BARBECUE,
IT'S RIGHT IN THERE.
TAKES ON A MEXICAN CLASSIC.
COCHINITA PIBIL.
YES.
PEOPLE JUST LOVE IT. IT'S,
LIKE, THE BEST TACO DISH EVER.
WE'RE IN BURBANK, ILLINOIS,
JUST SOUTHWEST OF CHI-TOWN
TO CHECK OUT CHUCK'S
SOUTHERN COMFORTS CAFé.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH,
BRUNSWICK STEW AND GREEN BEANS.
CHUCK'S IS TO DIE FOR.
WONDERFUL, WONDERFUL FOOD.
CHICKEN ENCHILADAS.
CHICKEN-FRIED CHICKEN.
THANK YOU.
YOU HAVE THAT CHILDHOOD COMFORT
TO IT WITH AN ADULT SPIN ON IT.
I NEED A SETUP
FOR PORK WITH GREEN MOLE.
(man) GOT IT.
(man) YOU CAN TELL
THAT CHUCK ENJOYS COOKING.
YOU CAN TELL
THAT HIS HEART'S IN IT.
HOW ARE YOU GUYS DOING
OUT HERE?
I'M GOOD.
HOW ARE YOU?
DOING GOOD? I'M GOOD.
THAT'D BE CHEF AND OWNER
CHUCK PINE
WHO'S BEEN COOKING UP CLASSIC
SOUTHERN COMFORT FOOD HIS WAY
FOR 13 YEARS.
WE DO SOUTHERN FOODS.
FULL SLAB OF RIBS
GOING IN THE WINDOW.
OH, IT'S UNBELIEVABLE,
THE SMOKINESS, THE FLAVORS,
THE BARBECUE,
IT'S RIGHT IN THERE.
WE STARTED OUT
AS A BARBECUE PLACE
AND JUST KIND OF SLOWLY
BUT SURELY KEPT ADDING STUFF.
STUFF LIKE SCRATCH-MADE CAJUN
AND SPICY HOT TEX-MEX.
CAJUN MEAT LOAF IN THE WINDOW.
I GOT THE COCHINITA.
HE'S EVEN SERVING UP A TASTE
OF THE YUCATáN.
COCHINITA PIBIL
IN THE WINDOW.
COCHINITA PIBIL.
THANK YOU.
IT'S GREAT COMBINATION OF
FLAVORS, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE TEX-MEX, A LITTLE BIT
OF SOUTHERN GOING ON.
IT'S REALLY GREAT.
(Chuck) IT'S PORK
THAT'S SLOW-ROASTED.
NORMALLY, IT'S BURIED
UNDERGROUND.
IT'S SHREDDED AFTERWARDS
AND SERVED IN ITS OWN JUICE.
AND HERE WE DO IT IN A PAN.
BUT HE KEEPS IT OLD-SCHOOL
BY USING BANANA LEAVES
INSTEAD OF FOIL
TO LINE THE PAN.
WE LAY OUR BANANA LEAVES IN
AND THEN THROW IN
OUR PORK ON TOP.
WE'RE PROBABLY GOING THROUGH
100 PORK BUTTS A WEEK.
WE'RE MAKING THE ACHIOTE PASTE--
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
ACHIOTE, GARLIC, ORANGE JUICE,
SALT, OREGANO, BLACK PEPPER.
THEN WE JUST MAKE SURE
WE GET THE ACHIOTE RUB IN THERE
REALLY GOOD.
MY MAIN PHILOSOPHY
IS THAT YOU WANT STUFF
TO BE COMPLETELY SEASONED.
I DON'T WANT THE CUSTOMER
TO HAVE ADD
A BUNCH OF SALT AND PEPPER
AND DUMP KETCHUP ON IT.
I COVER IT
WITH SLICED YELLOW ONIONS,
TOP IT WITH BANANA LEAVES
AND THEN FOIL,
AND THEN WE POP IT IN THE OVEN.
12 HOURS LATER,
THE BANANA LEAVES HAVE
STEAMED UP SOME RIGHTEOUS PORK
AND GIVEN IT A LITTLE FLAVOR.
NOW THAT WE'VE ROASTED OFF
THE PORK,
WE DRAIN THE JUICES INTO A POT,
REDUCE THAT UNTIL
IT'S GOT A NICE STRONG FLAVOR.
NEXT, WE TAKE OUR COCHINITA
OUT OF THE PAN,
THROW IT IN THE SMOKER
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
LET IT GET A LITTLE SMOKE,
A LITTLE CRISPY OUTSIDE MEAT.
THEN WE SHRED IT UP,
HIT IT WITH THE PAN JUICES.
IT'S READY TO SERVE.
WE LIKE TO SERVE AN HABANERO
SALSA WITH OUR COCHINITA PIBIL.
WE START OUT
BY ROASTING RED ONIONS, GARLIC,
GREEN ONIONS, AND HABANEROS.
NOW WE'RE TAKING
OUR ROASTED VEGGIES,
PUTTING 'EM IN THE BLENDER,
ADDING OUR ORANGE JUICE,
LIME JUICE, CILANTRO,
SALT, AND SUGAR.
COCHINITA PIBIL.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
PEOPLE JUST LOVE IT. IT'S,
LIKE, THE BEST TACO DISH EVER.
THE MEAT IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
HOW'S THE COCHINITA?
OH, I LOVE IT, MAN.
IS IT GOOD? ONE BRISKET
SANDWICH, FRIES, AND SLAW.
IT'S WORTH
STUFFING YOURSELF,
LOOSENING THE PANTS,
AND GOING HOME.
(woman) CATFISH PO'BOY.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE NEEDED A PLACE
LIKE THIS HERE.
BUT AS COMPLEX
AS THIS FOOD GETS,
IT'S PRETTY SIMPLE
FOR CHUCK.
(Chuck)
WHAT I DO LIKE TO DO HERE
IS SERVE ALL THE KIND OF FOOD
THAT I LIKE.
YOU KNOW, LIKE, I LOVE BARBECUE.
I LOVE MEXICAN.
I LOVE CAJUN FOOD.
IT'S JUST GREAT FOOD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE RECIPES
FROM SOME
OF THE JOINTS WE VISITED,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
THROW IT.
WHAT IS THAT
OVER THERE?
YOU THREW IT IN.
NOW THEY'RE GONNA BE WRONG.