HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
AND THEN YOU JUST START
SHREDDING IT ACROSS THERE.
FROM KRAUT...
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
TO COUSCOUS...
HERE'S YOUR LAMB COUSCOUS.
IT'S FABULOUS.
OUTSIDE DENVER...
A DOZEN ORIGINALS
GOING IN.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
EVERYTHING HERE TASTES HOMEMADE.
DOING BURGER POCKETS...
LOOK AT THAT.
FILLED WITH KRAUT...
MMM. IT'S LIKE
A MEAT PRETZEL.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
HOW IS THE FOOD?
THE FAMILY JOINT...
EXCELLENT, SURPRISING.
WHERE THEY'RE ROCKIN'...
(Guy) A LOT OF LAMB.
THE MOROCCAN...
I GOT THE MECHOUI COMING UP.
RICH FLAVOR.
MMM, DELICIOUS.
AND IN TAMPA...
STEAK FOR THE BURRITO
GOING DOWN.
THE LOCAL HANGOUT...
THE ONLY PLACE
I COME AROUND FOR TACOS.
DOING IT CALI STYLE...
(man) FISH TACOS, LOADED.
MMM. THAT'S A TACO
LIKE YOU COULD FIND IN CALI.
AND MORE.
FRIES FOR
THE CALIFORNIA BURRITO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
I'M ABOUT 20 MILES NORTH
OF DENVER, COLORADO,
IN A LITTLE FARMING COMMUNITY
CALLED BRIGHTON
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S SERVING UP
FOURTH-GENERATION
GERMAN FAMILY RECIPES
AND SOMETHING CALLED
A KRAUT BURGER.
NOW IF YOU'RE EXPECTING A BURGER
WITH A BUNCH OF KRAUT ON TOP,
OH, HO HO, YOU GOT
ANOTHER THING COMING.
THIS IS LAUER-KRAUTS.
(woman) KRAUT BURGERS READY.
THERE'S NOTHING BETTER
THAN A LAUER-KRAUT BURGER.
KRAUT BURGER WITH HAMBURGER,
HOMEMADE KRAUT.
I'VE GOT
A BIG TO-GO ORDER.
IT'S JUST BAKED IN
A HOMEMADE BREAD POCKET.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
IT'S LIKE THIS KRAUT BURGER
VILLAGE OR SOMETHING.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
THE SAUERKRAUT.
THAT OWNER ROBIN TRUJILLO
HAS BEEN EATING...
A DOZEN ORIGINALS
GOING IN.
HER WHOLE LIFE.
MY DAD'S ALWAYS MADE
HIS HOMEMADE SAUERKRAUT,
AND HE CALLS IT
LAUER-KRAUT.
LAUER IS MY MAIDEN NAME.
OH.
AND FOUR YEARS AGO...
ONE ORIGINAL.
SHE TOOK HER DAD'S LAUER-KRAUT
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
ORIGINAL LAUER-KRAUT BURGER.
A RECIPE SHE'LL BE PASSING ON
SOMEDAY.
YOU'RE NINE MONTHS PREGNANT?
I AM.
COME DOWN AND MEET
THE KRAUT BURGER BABY
COMING SOON.
(laughs)
I LOVE THESE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
A KRAUT BURGER.
YOU'RE GONNA HAND-SLICE
ALL THIS CABBAGE.
WE ARE.
NO, NO, NO, YOU.
(laughs)
I DON'T KNOW WHERE YOU
GOT THIS, BUT I'M GETTING ONE.
AWESOME!
THAT'S MY GRANDPA LAUER'S,
ACTUALLY.
AND WHAT'S IT CALLED?
A HOBEL--
A CABBAGE SHREDDER.
LET'S SEE
HOW THIS GOES.
WE QUARTER IT
AND PUT IT INTO THE GUIDE,
AND THEN YOU JUST START
SHREDDING IT ACROSS THERE.
SO WE SHRED ALL THE CABBAGE,
AND THEN...
WE START ADDING IT
TO THE CROCK.
THEN WE SALT IT.
AND YOU START MASHING IT BY
HAND, AND IT STARTS TO JUICE.
SO THE SALT DRAWS OUT
THE MOISTURE, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
AND THEN WE JUST KEEP ADDING
MORE CABBAGE, ADDING MORE SALT.
AND YOU JUST
KEEP FROTHING IT.
AND THIS JUST
GOES ON AND ON AND ON.
UNTIL WE HAVE
A FULL CROCK.
ALL FOR SAUERKRAUT?
WE'RE GLUTTONS
FOR PUNISHMENT.
AND THEN THAT
GETS A LID?
YEAH,
THEN WE WEIGHT IT.
PRESS IT.
MM-HMM.
NOW HOW LONG DOES
THE SAUERKRAUT FERMENT?
28 DAYS.
AND AFTER 28 DAYS...
IT'S DONE,
AND IT'S REALLY MILD AND...
MMM.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S KILLER KRAUT.
IT'S WORTH ALL THE EFFORT.
WE THINK SO.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS OUR FILLING
FOR OUR LAUER-KRAUT BURGERS.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
FIRST TO GO IN,
OUR 80/20 GROUND CHUCK.
SO YOU BROWN UP ALL THE MEAT.
NOW WHAT GOES IN?
NEXT GOES OUR ONIONS.
THEN SALT...
SALT.
AND BLACK PEPPER,
CABBAGE.
YEP.
THAT GETS STIRRED IN.
ANOTHER ONE.
STIR IT IN.
LAST ONE.
MORE CABBAGE.
THAT'S AWESOME.
SALT AND PEPPER.
ADD THE LAUER-KRAUT.
YEP.
IT ALL GETS STIRRED TOGETHER
AND IT COOKS FOR 15 MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'LL BE READY
TO STRAIN.
WE'LL LET IT COOL, AND THEN
WE'LL ADD IT TO THE DOUGH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR BREAD
DOUGH FOR OUR KRAUT BURGERS.
WE DO THE DOUGH.
SO HERE GOES MY YEAST...
WITH A LITTLE SUGAR...
AND WARM WATER,
A LITTLE STIR.
THEN WE'RE GONNA BLOOM IT.
A MAD SCIENTIST OVER HERE.
THEN MY DRY MILK--
PUT SOME WATER IN IT, TOO.
GIVE THAT A LITTLE STIR.
THEN WHILE THAT RISES,
I'LL START WITH MY FLOUR, SALT.
IN GOES MY SHORTENING.
I'M JUST GONNA CUT THIS IN.
AND ADD OUR EGGS,
CUT THAT IN.
YOU DO THIS BY HAND
ALL THE TIME?
YEP.
THERE YOU GO.
THEN WE ADD OUR DRY MILK,
THEN THE YEAST.
YOU'RE GONNA KNEAD THIS?
WE KNEAD IT
RIGHT IN THE BOWL.
AND HOW MANY KRAUT BURGERS
WILL THIS MAKE?
ABOUT 18 KRAUT BURGERS.
HOW MANY KRAUT BURGERS
DO YOU SELL IN A DAY?
UPWARDS OF 200.
YOU DO THIS
TEN TIMES A DAY?
AT LEAST.
THIS WAY, I DON'T HAVE
TO GO TO THE GYM.
YEAH, YOU JUST WALK AROUND
WITH ONE BIG, HUGE ARM.
(laughs)
NOW WE'LL FORM IT INTO A BALL,
COVER IT, AND LET IT RISE.
I'M GONNA PUNCH THE DOUGH.
FLOUR THE TABLE. DUMP IT OUT.
PUT A LITTLE FLOUR ON TOP.
FLIP IT OVER.
NOW WE'LL ROLL IT OUT.
OH. JUST KEEP
DOING THIS.
I'LL HAVE, LIKE, 20 POUNDS
OF THIS FILLING IN ME. MMM.
I'M GONNA TAKE MY
BIG SQUARE KNIFE, CUT IT.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
I TAKE A PIECE OF THE DOUGH,
AND I ROLL IT YET AGAIN.
AND THEN GIVE IT A FLIP.
STRETCH IT A BIT.
TAKE A FULL CUP OF FILLING.
PLOP IT DOWN IN THE MIDDLE.
WOW.
AND BRING IT UP
AND START PINCHING.
SEAL IT UP GOOD.
MMM.
CAN YOU MAKE ONE
WITH CHEESE?
PEPPER JACK CHEESE
OR AMERICAN CHEESE?
TUCK THE CORNERS.
AND THAT'S IT.
THROW 'EM ON THE TRAY,
IN THE OVEN.
IN THE OVEN THEY GO,
15 MINUTES AT 350.
ALL RIGHT,
THEY'RE READY TO COME OUT.
OH.
OH, OH, OH.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
THAT'S LIKE A MEAT PRETZEL.
THIS IS CRAZY.
THE PEPPER--OHH, PRIME TIME.
THE NICE TENDER BUN--
IT'S MOIST. IT'S SOFT.
IT'S DOUGHY.
IT'S PRETZEL-LIKE.
JUST FOR SENSE
OF TELEVISION AND SCIENCE,
I'M GONNA TRY ONE
WITH CHEESE. MMM. OH, YEAH.
WHERE HAVE THESE BEEN
ALL MY LIFE? NICE JOB.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS.
(man) LAUER-KRAUT ORIGINAL.
OH, IT'S JUST WONDERFUL.
THE CABBAGE AND THE MEAT
IS FABULOUS.
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
ALL WITH HOMEMADE BREAD, WHICH
IS WHAT MAKES IT DELICIOUS.
AND ROBIN'S CRANKING OUT
1,000 A WEEK...
THIS DOZEN'S READY
FOR THE WARMER.
AND THIS TINY, 3-TABLE JOINT.
NOT A LOT OF PLACES
TO SIT.
THEY WERE SO CROWDED
THE OTHER DAY,
I JUST TOOK IT
AND ATE IT IN MY CAR.
AND THAT WORKS...
GOT ANOTHER TO-GO ORDER.
BECAUSE YOU CAN GET
THE WHOLE MENU TO GO,
FROM DESSERT...
GERMAN CHOCOLATE BROWNIE.
TO SAUSAGE WRAPS...
READY TO GO.
AND THEIR SCRATCH-MADE SOUPS.
AUNTIE'S BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
ANOTHER FAMILY RECIPE.
OUTSTANDING.
SO WHAT WERE WE MAKING?
THE EGG NOODLES
FOR OUR BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
WE DO AT LEAST FOUR BATCHES
OF NOODLES A DAY.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ADDING OUR FLOUR.
OKAY.
PUT THE LID ON THIS.
START IT RUNNING.
STREAM IN THE EGGS.
AND I HAVE TO SHAKE IT.
IT MIGHT BE
ON ITS LAST PASTA BATCH.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
TILL I SEE IT FORMING.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU CAN HEAR IT.
AND THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
THEN I DUMP IT TO THE TABLE.
I FORM A BALL.
AND IT RESTS
FOR A MINIMUM OF 30 MINUTES.
FOLLOW THE BALL.
OKAY, PICK IT.
(gasps)
IT'S MAGIC.
AH HA HA!
THEN I KIND OF
JUST FORM IT.
OKAY.
CUT IT INTO SIX PORTIONS.
THEN I FLATTEN IT OUT A BIT.
SO IT'LL GO THROUGH
THE MACHINE.
THEN I GO THROUGH ANOTHER.
IT'LL GET 'EM A LITTLE THINNER.
THEY GO THROUGH AGAIN.
NO FLOUR ON THIS.
NOPE, THEN ONCE THEY START
TO DRY A LITTLE BIT,
I JUST GIVE 'EM A FLIP,
DRY 'EM JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE.
OKAY, NOW WE CUT.
WE'RE DOING A FETTUCCINE CUT.
YOU JUST KEEP KNOCKING THIS OUT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SOUP
WITH THIS?
CORRECT.
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
NOW WE ARE GONNA
PRESSURE OUR HAM
TO START THE BROTH
FOR OUR BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
WE USE THE SHANK PORTION
SO WE GET THE NICE BIG BONE.
AND JUST WATER
AND THEN PUT THE LID ON.
THAT'S A PRESSURE COOKER.
CRANK THE HEAT.
THEN IT GOES
FOR 45 MINUTES.
AND THEN WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO
WITH THE REST OF THE HAM?
WE LEAVE THE BONE
IN THERE,
AND WE ADD THE REST OF THE HAM
IN THE PRESSURE COOKER,
AND THAT GOES
FOR ANOTHER 30 MINUTES.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
NOW WE'RE GONNA COOL IT.
WE'RE GONNA SCOOP OUT THE MEAT.
OKAY.
STRAIN THE BROTH
AND CUBE UP THE HAM.
FINALLY, IT'S TIME TO MAKE
THE FAMOUS BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR CUBED HAM,
ADD OUR STRAINED BROTH.
OKAY.
PINTO BEANS GO IN,
A LITTLE HAM BASE.
AND THEN WE ADD A LITTLE WATER
TO FILL UP THE POT.
BRING IT TO A BOIL.
THEN WE ADD THE NOODLES.
AND THEN IT SIMMERS
10 TO 15 MINUTES.
NOW WE ADD OUR MIXTURE
OF CREAMS.
THERE'S CREAM IN THIS?
SOUR CREAM, HEAVY CREAM,
AND EVAPORATED MILK.
THIS IS REALLY STRANGE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD SALT, PEPPER,
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
STIR THAT IN.
AND WHAT IS THIS?
(speaking indistinctly)
READY?
YEP.
AND THAT'S
BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
AND HOW DO WE
SERVE IT?
WE EITHER SERVE IT
IN A CUP OR IN A BREAD BOWL.
I WANT A BREAD BOWL.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL DO BREAD BOWL.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
IT'S REALLY
THICKENED UP NICE.
OKAY. MMM.
COOKING THE NOODLE
IN THE BROTH
MAKES THAT NOODLE REALLY HAVE
A LOT OF FLAVOR. MMM.
THESE JUST COOK
TO WHERE THEY ALMOST DISSOLVE
RIGHT WHEN YOU PUT 'EM
IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S NOT HEAVY LIKE A CHOWDER,
BUT IT'S VERY RICH
WITH THE BEANS
AND WITH THE PASTA, MMM,
AND THE SALTINESS OF THE HAM--
GREAT FLAVOR.
DEFINITELY SOMETHING
I'D HAVE AGAIN. GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
(man) IT'S DELICIOUS.
THERE YOU GUYS GO.
THE FLAVOR'S REALLY GREAT.
IT'S A COMBINATION I'VE NEVER
HAD ANYWHERE BUT HERE.
THE NOODLES ARE LIKE NO NOODLES
I'VE EVER HAD BEFORE.
BEAN AND NOODLE SOUP.
EVERYTHING HERE
TASTES HOMEMADE.
WE GOT ANOTHER TO-GO ORDER.
LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING--
YOU'RE A HARD WORKER.
YOU HAVE A TON OF PASSION
ABOUT THIS.
I AM SO GLAD
I DON'T LIVE IN THIS TOWN.
I'D BE HERE THREE TIMES
A WEEK. AWESOME JOB.
UP NEXT...
HALF CHICKEN WITH RICE
AND BASTILLA.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO SAN ANTONIO...
I'VE BEEN ALL AROUND. I'VE NEVER
HAD ANY FOOD LIKE THIS.
FOR WHAT ELSE?
AUTHENTIC MOROCCAN.
WOW, I CAN'T
STOP EATING IT.
SO I GET THE GREAT JOB
OF TRAVELIN' AROUND THE COUNTRY
AND FINDING FUNKY JOINTS
IN UNIQUE PLACES.
SO GUESS WHERE I AM?
SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
RIGHT OUTSIDE THE LOOP
OF THE 410 FREEWAY
BY FORT SAM HOUSTON
TO CHECK OUT A REAL-DEAL,
FAMILY-RUN MOROCCAN RESTAURANT.
YEP, THIS IS MOROCCAN BITES.
YOUR MERGUEZ IS READY,
NADIA.
(Nadia) YES, MA.
TABLE FOUR, KEFTA TAGINS.
LAMB AND BEEF MEATBALLS--IT'S
ONE OF MY ABSOLUTE FAVORITES.
(man) COUSCOUS WITH LAMB.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF MOROCCAN FOOD?
EXCELLENT.
IT'S SURPRISING.
I'VE BEEN ALL AROUND. I'VE NEVER
HAD ANY FOOD LIKE THIS.
CHICKEN BASTILLA.
CHICKEN AND POWDERED SUGAR.
YOU'D THINK IT'S VERY ODD,
BUT IT IS AMAZINGLY GOOD.
YOU JUST DON'T EXPECT FLAVORS
LIKE THIS TO COME OUT.
(man) KAFTA KEBAB.
IT'S LIKE EATING FOOD PREPARED
BY YOUR OWN MOROCCAN MOTHER.
MOM, LAMB KEBAB.
OR THIS MOM...
LAMB KEBAB PLATE.
LATIFA EL MAROUDI...
HOW IS THE FOOD?
WONDERFUL.
WHO OPENED THIS JOINT
AFTER COMIN' TO THE STATES
TO BE WITH HER KIDS.
THAT LOOKS YUMMY.
THAT'S HER DREAM
TO OPEN A RESTAURANT.
YEAH, THE WHOLE FAMILY'S
WORKING HERE WITH HER.
KEBDA WITH LENTILS.
WAFA AND YOUSSEFF
OUT FRONT...
(man) HUMMUS.
AND NADIA IN THE KITCHEN.
HALF CHICKEN
WITH RICE AND BASTILLA.
HELPING COOK UP
MAMA'S RECIPES...
RICE FOR THE MECHOUI.
LIKE THIS MOROCCAN CLASSIC...
MECHOUI READY.
LAMB ROASTED IN A SPICE RUB.
REALLY NICE COMBO OF FLAVORS.
EVERYBODY NEEDS TO TRY IT.
OKAY, NADIA E.,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
THE MECHOUI.
IS THAT A TRADITIONAL
MOROCCAN...
MOROCCAN DISH.
NOW HOW DO WE
START IT?
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE FIRST
WITH THE SAFFRON,
AND WE WARM IT
A LITTLE BIT.
WE WARM IT
YES, SIR.
PUT THE SAFFRON
IN THE TINFOIL,
IN THE PAN,
AND THEN TO THE STOVE.
SO THAT LITTLE BIT OF SAFFRON
IS FOR THE WHOLE LAMB.
YES, SIR.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
I CRUSH IT WITH A SPOON.
LET ME MOVE SOME OF THIS
OUT OF THE WAY.
HOLY SHEET PAN, BATMAN,
A MINI HOT TUB.
GINGER...
(whistles)
REAL PREDOMINANT SPICE
IN MOROCCAN FOOD?
YES, SIR.
SALT, GARLIC POWDER.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THIS BINDLE IS.
OKAY,
MOROCCAN YELLOW SAFFRON.
IT'S LIKE TURMERIC,
SO IT'S GONNA
PUT A REAL NICE COLOR TO IT.
YES, MM-HMM.
(whistles)
IT'S LIKE NACHO CHEESE POWDER.
IS THIS THE SAUCE
THE SALT NEEDS TO GO IN?
YES, SIR, MM-HMM.
OKAY.
SOME WATER.
AND RUB IT TOGETHER.
MM-HMM. MORE WATER.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
ALL RIGHT.
HERE WE GO.
OH!
A LOT OF LAMB.
YOU TUCK THE LEG UP
UNDERNEATH?
YES, SIR.
RUB ALL THIS IN.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO WITH
THE BUTTER, PUT IT ON THE TOP?
MM-HMM.
AND WE COVER IT
WITH THE FOIL.
THE FOIL.
NOW IT'S GOING TO THE COOLER
OVERNIGHT TO MARINATE.
WHEN THE LAMB IS READY
TO GO TO THE OVEN,
I ADD IN 2 MORE CUPS OF WATER,
I COVER IT,
AND I ROAST IT
FOR FIVE HOURS.
I'M GETTING THE LAMB OUT.
IT SMELLS GOOD. (whistles)
THERE WE GO.
CHECK THAT OUT.
OH, GET OUT OF HERE.
LOOK AT THE MEAT.
I MEAN, JUST TALK ABOUT
FALL-APART TENDER. MMM.
REALLY RICH FLAVOR,
REALLY MOIST.
MMM, THE TUNE THAT YOU'RE
PLAYING RIGHT HERE,
I'VE HEARD IT BEFORE--
IT'S CALLED DELICIOUS.
OH, I CAN'T STOP EATING.
GREAT JOB.
(man) HERE'S YOUR MECHOUI.
THIS IS ONE
OF MY FAVORITES.
THE WAY THEY FIX IT,
IT'S VERY TENDER.
MECHOUI READY.
IT'S VERY JUICY,
GREAT COMBO OF FLAVORS.
HERE IS YOUR
MERGUEZ SANDWICH.
I LOVE EVERYTHING
THAT I'VE TRIED.
EVERYTHING IS OKAY?
BECAUSE MAMA'S ALWAYS HERE...
SUGAR, PUT SUGAR.
TO MAKE SURE IT'S DONE RIGHT.
OKAY, GOOD.
I'M FROM MOROCCO,
AND I FEEL LIKE I'M HOME HERE.
MECHOUI AND EGGPLANT.
YOU CAN EXPERIENCE SOMETHING NEW
EVERY SINGLE TIME.
KEBDA IS READY.
FROM MARINATED LAMB LIVER...
VERY TENDER AND SUCCULENT.
TO MINT TEA...
IT'S SO GOOD.
AND THIS CLASSIC...
COUSCOUS DONE.
A FRIDAY NIGHT
MOROCCAN FAMILY TRADITION.
IT'S VERY FAMOUS BACK HOME
ON MOROCCAN FRIDAYS.
(man)
HERE'S YOUR LAMB COUSCOUS.
WELL, I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
THIS IS AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
FIRST THE COUSCOUS.
JUST SO YOU KNOW, THAT'S NOT
GRAIN. THAT'S A LITTLE PASTA.
WE'LL PUT SOME OLIVE OIL
AT THE BEGINNING,
MIX IT TOGETHER,
SOME WATER.
MORE WATER.
ARE YOU MEASURING
THE WATER?
NO.
YOU'RE JUST
GETTING A FEEL?
JUST GETTING
A FEEL WITH MY...
OKAY.
AND LET IT RELAX FOR, LIKE,
10 SECONDS TO 20 SECONDS.
YOU'LL LET IT RELAX
FOR 10 TO 20 SECONDS?
YES, SIR.
HOW GRACIOUS OF YA.
WHAT'S FLOATING IN HERE, LEMONS?
YES.
NOW WE POUR IT
ON THE STEAMER TO STEAM.
WE'LL LEAVE IT
FOR TEN SECONDS.
OKAY.
SO WE MIX
THE SALT IN.
AND WE'RE GOING
TO ADD IN MORE WATER.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'RE GOING TO POUR IT
AGAIN ONE MORE TIME.
BACK ON TOP OF HERE.
YES, SIR.
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA GO THIS TIME?
FIVE TO TEN MINUTES.
NO COVER? GOT IT.
NO, SIR.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS WITH?
WE'RE GOING TO SERVE IT
WITH THE LAMB AND VEGETABLES.
LAMB AND VEGETABLES.
YES, SIR.
THE OIL FIRST.
LAMB SHANKS?
YES, SALT, GINGER,
BLACK PEPPER,
MOROCCANONION...SAFFRON,
CILANTRO AND PARSLEY.
TOMATOES, AND SOME WATER.
MIX EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
AND HOW LONG
IS IT GONNA COOK?
JUST, LIKE,
25 TO 30 MINUTES.
OKAY.
SO THE LAMB'S COOKED.
ALL THE VEGGIES IN.
YES, SIR, WE'RE GOING
TO ADD IN OUR CARROT...
WOW.
TURNIP, YELLOW SQUASH.
ZUCCHINI, GREEN SQUASH,
POTATOES...
POTATOES?
YES, AND BUTTER SQUASH...
BUTTER SQUASH.
TOMATO SAUCE.
IN MOROCCAN?
IN MOROCCAN FOOD--
AND WATER.
MAKE IT STEW.
HOW LONG?
ABOUT 35 MINUTES.
OKAY.
SO SERVE IT UP.
LOOK HOW LIGHT AND FLUFFY
THAT IS.
GOING TO GIVE THE MEAT
SOME CARROTS...
LOOK AT THAT.
SOME ZUCCHINI...
GOT A LITTLE POTATO
IN THERE, HUH?
NOW WE'RE GONNA GET THE JUICE.
I'M IN AWE.
THE COLORS, I'LL TELL YA, MY
MOUTH'S GOING BANANAS RIGHT NOW.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
LET'S CHECK THIS LAMB OUT.
MMM, PRETTY TENDER.
LOOK AT THAT.
ANY TIME THE MEAT'S COOKED
REALLY CLOSE TO THE BONE,
MMM, A LOT OF REALLY
BIG FLAVOR IN THERE.
THERE'S A SWEETNESS
WITH ALL THE VEGETABLES,
KIND OF TASTES LIKE THE STEW
THAT MY MOM WOULD MAKE.
MMM, AND THEN
THE COUSCOUS ITSELF,
THE INDIVIDUAL PIECES
OF THE PASTA,
ACTUALLY NICE AND LIGHT
AND FLUFFY, MMM.
GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
COUSCOUS LAMB WITH VEGETABLES.
IT'S FABULOUS.
THE TEXTURE'S QUITE LOVELY.
IT'S ALMOST AS IF THEY'RE
SEPARATING EACH GRAIN
TO MAKE IT
SO LIGHT AND FLUFFY.
YOU CAN'T COMPARE IT
TO ANYTHING, REALLY.
DYNAMITE.
ALL RIGHT, LISTEN.
WHEN WE COME BACK
TO SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
IT'S MORE ROCKIN' MOROCCAN
WITH NADIA.
(woman)
BOWL OF HUMMUS COMING UP.
EVERY CHICKPEA IS WHOLE.
IT'S TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THIS.
MMM. DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
WELCOME BACK
TO SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS.
WE'RE AT A JOINT
CALLED MOROCCAN BITES,
AND WE'RE HANGING OUT
WITH NADIA E. AND HER FAMILY
MAKING SOME ROCKIN' MOROCCAN.
HUMMUS.
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
WHAT IS THIS ONE CALLED,
LET'S GET EVERYTHING THAT
WE HAVE IN THE ENTIRE KITCHEN
AND PUT IT IN A DISH?
NOT EVERYTHING.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
MOROCCAN HUMMUS.
OKAY, GO FOR IT.
OLIVE OIL, CELERY,
GREEN PEPPER,
RED PEPPER, ONION, TURMERIC.
JUST EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL, HUH.
YES, SIR.
SOME GARLIC, PARSLEY,
SALT...
PAPRIKA.
CUMIN, GINGER...
LOVE THAT GINGER.
CORIANDER,
LOTS OF BAY LEAF.
RED PEPPER,
YELLOW SAFFRON...
LOVE THAT STUFF.
AND WATER.
MIX EVERYTHING.
OKAY.
THAT GOES
FOR 25 MINUTES?
YES, SIR.
AND NOW THE DEHYDRATED
CHICKPEAS--SERIOUS COLANDER--
AND THE TOMATO SAUCE.
TOMATO SAUCE.
AND WE'RE GONNA
PURéE IT?
NO, WE DON'T.
NO?
NO.
WE SERVE IT RUSTIC?
YES, SIR.
I LIKE IT. AND HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
ANOTHER 20 MINUTES
OR SO.
NOW THE HUMMUS
IS READY.
WAIT TILL YOU
SEE THIS.
THAT'S MOROCCAN HUMMUS.
LIKE VEGETARIAN
CHICKPEA STEW.
YES, SIR.
DO I EAT IT
LIKE STEW?
YOU'RE GOING TO EAT IT
THE MOROCCAN WAY WITH THE BREAD.
OKAY.
MMM, REALLY SAVORY BROTH,
BIG HEARTY TEXTURE.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S INTERESTING,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE IN THAT--
PICKING UP THE CHILI FLAKE
AND SOME OF THE BLACK PEPPER.
AND THE BREAD, MMM,
EXCELLENT. SUPERSTAR.
THANK YOU.
HERE'S YOUR HUMMUS PLATE
WITH MOROCCAN BREAD.
YOU GET ALL OF THESE TEXTURES
TOGETHER. IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE FLAVORS ARE GREAT.
THEY JUST EXPLODE IN YOUR MOUTH.
VERY, VERY FRESH.
JUST FANTASTIC.
IS THIS LIKE THE FOOD
THAT YOU HAD IN MOROCCO?
VERY MUCH.
REAL DEAL.
RIGHT DOWN
TO THIS TRADITIONAL SAUSAGE...
YOUR MERGUEZ IS READY.
MADE WITH TRADITIONAL SPICES...
SEVEN MOROCCAN SPICES.
SERVED UP IN A SANDWICH.
MERGUEZ SANDWICH.
IT'S REALLY GREAT HERE.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
MERGUEZ.
MERGUEZ, THE SAUSAGE.
YEAH, THE MOROCCAN SAUSAGE.
GOT IT.
FIRST,
WE TRIM THE BEEF.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO CLEAN THE LAMB.
SOME NICE WHITE LAMB FAT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GRIND IT?
YES, SIR.
YOU CALL ME SIR.
THAT'S IT, GUY.
GUY.
START WITH THE BEEF.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF LAMB,
A LITTLE BEEF.
THAT MEAT'S REALLY LEAN.
WHEN ARE YOU
GONNA PUT SOME FAT IN?
I DID ALREADY.
IT'S COMING OUT. LOOK.
OH, WAY TO LIVE
ON THE EDGE.
OKAY, WE RUN THIS THROUGH
HOW MANY TIMES?
TWO TIMES.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
WE GET
THE MOROCCAN SPICES.
TURMERIC, CLOVE,
THE NUTMEG...
CARDAMOM, BLACK PEPPER
AND CHILI PEPPER...
THE CINNAMON
AND THEN GINGER.
AND GINGER.
THIS IS THE COMMON SEVEN SPICES
IN MOROCCAN FOOD?
YES, SIR.
TOAST IT ALL UP.
MMM, SMELL THAT.
AND THEN WE'LL GRIND IT.
IT GETS BUSY IN THERE.
(whistles)
OH, YOU SHOULD SMELL THAT.
THAT'S CRAZY.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO PUT
THE MEAT IN THE MACHINE
SO WE CAN MIX IT
WITH ALL OF THE INGREDIENTS.
WE GOT SALT, PAPRIKA...
LOVE PAPRIKA.
CUMIN...
CORIANDER.
CRUSHED PEPPER, WATER--
THE SEVEN MOROCCAN SPICES.
OKAY, SO WE MIX THIS UP
TILL IT'S ALL INCORPORATED.
IT SMELLS AWESOME.
OKAY, SO OUR MIXTURE
OF OUR MEAT.
TO PUT INSIDE THE MACHINE
AND PUT IT INTO THE CASING.
I LIKE IT.
PUT THE CASING.
LAMB, PORK?
YES, LAMB.
LOOK AT IT. ALL RIGHT.
SO NOW YOU TIE A KNOT
AT THE END.
TINIEST KNOT I'VE EVER SEEN IN
MANKIND. SHE'S LIKE A SURGEON.
CRANK IT UP.
HERE IT COMES.
SO JUST RUN 'EM ALL OUT,
AND THEN TWIST 'EM? I LIKE THIS.
MM-HMM.
LET IT REST
FOR A COUPLE HOURS?
YES, SIR.
ON THE GRILL?
YES.
THEN THE BREAD
LIKE THIS OR LIKE THIS?
JUST LIKE THIS.
OKAY. SO TELL ME
WHAT'S IN THE RELISH.
OLIVE OIL, ONION, TOMATOES,
GREEN OLIVES,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
WE COOK THIS
FOR 15 TO 20 MINUTES.
OKAY.
WE'LL LET IT COOL.
AFTER THAT,
IT GOES ON THE SANDWICH.
AND WE PUT
OUR SAUSAGE IN.
AND THAT'S IT.
OH,
THAT IS REALLY GOOD.
THE MEAT WAS REALLY LEAN,
AND THERE'S A LOT OF FLAVOR.
MMM.
YOU GET THAT SEVEN-SPICE,
A LITTLE TEXTURE OF THE CLOVE,
A LITTLE TOUCH
OF THE CARDAMOM--MMM.
THAT RELISH IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
AWESOME SANDWICH.
I'M GLAD
YOU LIKE IT, SIR.
LIKE IT? I LOVE IT.
HERE'S YOUR
MERGUEZ SANDWICH.
IT HAS WONDERFUL SPICES.
VERY FLAVORFUL.
REALLY NICE TEXTURE.
MERGUEZ IS READY.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
WHAT MAKES IT
IS THE RELISH
THAT THEY PUT ON.
OH, RELISH
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
AND YOUR LAMB TAGINE
WITH VEGETABLES.
IT'S GREAT.
THEY JUST REALLY ENJOY
WHAT THEY DO, AND IT SHOWS.
YOU WAIT TILL YOUR
TRIPLE "D" FAMILY SHOWS UP.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
IN BIG TROUBLE.
YOU GUYS GOTTA
COME CHECK THIS OUT.
NEXT STOP...
SHREDDED BEEF TACO.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO FLORIDA...
GOOD FOOD, FRESH.
IT'S GREAT.
FOR A TASTE OF CALIFORNIA.
FRIES FOR
THE CALIFORNIA BURRITO.
INSTEAD OF RICE AND BEANS--
THAT IS CALI.
NOW YOU KNOW YOU CAN FIND
FANTASTIC LATIN FOOD
WHEN YOU'RE IN FLORIDA.
SO HERE I AM CRUISING THROUGH
TAMPA ON BEARSS AVENUE,
AND I SEE A JOINT CALLED
CALIFORNIA TACOS,
WELL, YOU KNOW I GOTTA STOP
AND CHECK IT OUT.
TIJUANA PORK TACOS.
I LIKE IT A LOT. IT'S THE ONLY
PLACE I COME AROUND FOR TACOS.
SHREDDED BEEF TACO.
SORT OF A SWEET TEXTURE
TO IT.
IT'S DEFINITELY DIFFERENT
FROM ANY OTHER TACO PLACE
I'VE BEEN TO.
MORE LIKE THE KIND OF PLACE
CHARLIE MORRELL FELL IN LOVE
WITH LIVING IN SAN DIEGO...
STEAK FOR THE BURRITO
GOING DOWN.
WHERE THEY'RE PUTTING CABBAGE
ON FISH TACOS...
THE CABBAGE
IS DEFINITELY DIFFERENT.
FRENCH FRIES IN A BURRITO...
FRIES FOR
THE CALIFORNIA BURRITO.
INSTEAD OF RICE AND BEANS--
THAT IS CALI.
AND THE DINING ROOM...
I'LL CALL YOU WHEN IT'S READY,
OKAY? THANK YOU, BUDDY.
THANKS.
IT'S OUTSIDE...
EVERYTHING IS TO-GO.
HANGING OUT IS OPTIONAL.
AND POPULAR.
EVERY TIME
I GO OUT WITH FRIENDS,
THEY WANT TO GO SOMEWHERE,
"LET'S GO TO CALI TACO."
AND GET THIS CALI CLASSIC...
TWO FISH TACOS--
YOU GOT IT, MAN.
THEY'RE THE BEST.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WHITE FISH SAUCE
FOR OUR FISH TACOS.
OKAY.
FIRST, TAKE SOME CUMIN,
CAPERS, FRESH DILL...
OH, A LITTLE MEXICAN OREGANO,
MY FAVORITE OREGANO.
SOME NICE, GOOD
CHILE DE ARBOLS...
STEMMED BUT DID LEAVE
THE SEEDS IN 'EM.
GOTTA HAVE THAT FLAVOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
MAYONNAISE, YOGURT.
DEFINITELY HAVE THE CALIFORNIA
THING GOING THERE.
OH, YEAH.
FRESH SQUEEZED LIME,
MIX IT UP.
BRING IT ALL TOGETHER.
MMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT, A LITTLE
BIT OF THAT OREGANO IN THERE.
I LIKE THE BALANCE
OF THE YOGURT.
THAT IS SOME SUPER SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME TEMPURA BATTER.
FLOUR, CORNSTARCH,
BAKING POWDER, SALT.
OKAY.
MIX UP ALL THOSE
DRY INGREDIENTS.
A COUPLE EGGS.
OKAY.
LIKE SO.
A LITTLE BIT OF BEER.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP. NOW WE'RE
GONNA ADD TWO MORE EGGS.
MORE BEER.
WHY ARE WE DOING IT
IN TWO SEPARATE MIXES LIKE THAT?
IT DISTRIBUTES BETTER.
IT TASTES BETTER.
A LITTLE MORE FLOUR
IN THERE.
SO IT STICKS
TO THE FISH.
EXACTLY. THERE WE GO.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
WHAT KIND OF FISH
DO WE USE IN THIS TACO?
GROUPER.
BIG, HUGE CHUNKS
LIKE THAT.
YEAH, ABOUT 2 OUNCES
OR SO.
THAT'S A BIG 2 OUNCES,
BUDDY.
A COUPLE OF FRESH TORTILLAS
ON THE GRILL.
DOUBLING UP THE TACO.
WE PUT A LOT OF STUFF
ON IT.
THEY GOTTA STAY
GOOD AND CONSISTENT.
DROP SOME FISH
IN THE BATTER.
MAKE SURE YOU COAT IT
ALL THE WAY.
STRAIGHT INTO THE FRYER.
TORTILLA'S ABOUT READY.
PUT 'EM IN THE TO-GO CONTAINER.
OUT OF THE FRYER.
HE JUST DOESN'T
STOP TALKING.
PIECES OF NICE FISH
IN THERE.
(whistles)
WE GOT OUR WHITE SAUCE
RIGHT HERE...
THE SAUCE IS DYNAMITE.
CABBAGE...
LOVE CABBAGE
ON MY FISH TACOS.
IT MAKES THE CRUNCH
SO MUCH BETTER.
MEDIUM SALSA ON THERE,
A LITTLE SOUR CREAM,
GUACAMOLE...
OKAY.
SHREDDED CHEDDAR,
SOME MOZZARELLA,
A LITTLE TOUCH OF PICO,
A COUPLE OF FRESH LIMES
TO SQUEEZE ON THOSE TACOS,
AND THEY'RE READY TO GO.
DUDE, LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
MMM. FISH IS NICE AND TENDER,
NICE TEXTURE.
GUACAMOLE'S NICE AND FRESH,
THIN DOUBLE TORTILLA, I LIKE.
THAT WHITE SAUCE, MMM,
THAT TIES IT ALL TOGETHER.
MY FAVORITE, THOUGH,
THAT YOU DO REALLY WELL,
IS THAT CABBAGE
IS SUPER THIN-SLICED.
MMM, THAT'S A TACO
LIKE YOU CAN FIND IN CALI.
(Charlie) FISH TACOS, LOADED.
IT'S VERY FLAVORFUL.
THEY GIVE YOU
CHUNKS OF FISH.
THE SAUCE--WONDERFUL.
WORDS CAN'T DESCRIBE.
(Charlie) ENCHILADAS, LOADED.
GOOD FOOD, FRESH.
IT'S GREAT.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
HEY, PLEASURE, BRO.
YOU GOTTA COME
TO CALI.
SO WAS THAT A KILLER ROAD TRIP
OR WHAT?
HEY, LISTEN, IF YOU
WANT TO GET THESE RECIPES,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND DON'T WORRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
ALL RIGHT,
BE RIGHT BACK.
(laughs)