HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
NICE AND FRESH
AND WHOLESOME.
GETTIN' FRESH...
(man)
WE HAVE OUR DUCK LEGS.
ALL FREE-RANGE?
YEP.
OH, CAN'T BEAT THAT.
IN BOULDER, COLORADO...
ALL RIGHT, THERE YOU GUYS GO.
THE CAMPUS FAVORITE...
TONS OF STUDENTS
COME HERE AFTER CLASS.
PUTTIN' A FRESH SPIN...
PESTO--
MIX THE TWO TOGETHER.
MMM.
ON CAMPUS FAVORITES...
GOOD PIE.
IN CHICAGO...
SMOKED PORK SHOULDER.
THE FAMILY JOINT...
EVERYTHING IS FABULOUS.
SCRATCH-MAKING BISCUITS...
(whistles)
AND TOPPIN' 'EM
WITH WHAT ELSE?
DUCK CONFIT GRAVY.
YOU SEE IT EVERY DAY.
AND IN NORFOLK, VIRGINIA...
CRAB CAKE SANDWICH.
THE FARMERS' MARKET CAFé...
YOU CAN'T GET BETTER
LOCAL-GROWN FOOD.
WHERE GETTIN' FRESH...
SPRINKLE THAT ALL OVER.
MEANS MEAT LOAF.
DELICIOUS.
OVER THE TOP.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN BOULDER,
HOME OF THE UNIVERSITY
OF COLORADO BUFFALOES.
NOW IN A TOWN LIKE THIS,
YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND
A FEW COLLEGE HANGOUTS
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING
TYPICAL BAR FOOD.
YOU KNOW I'M STOKED
WHEN I FIND ONE
THAT'S SCRATCH-MAKING
THEIR PIZZA DOUGH,
USING GRASS-FED BEEF,
AND BUYING LOCAL ORGANICS.
THIS IS THE SINK.
THE FOOD HERE IS AMAZING.
(man)
ONION STRING BURGER.
SO DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN TASTE HOW FRESH IT IS.
CALIFORNIA CHICKEN.
THE SINK IS PART
OF THE C.U. BOULDER.
HAS BEEN SINCE THE LATE 1800s.
IT WAS THE FIRST
FRATERNITY HOUSE FOR SIGMA NU.
BUT IT'S BEEN A RESTAURANT
SINCE 1923.
ALL THOSE YEARS, ALL THOSE
PEOPLE CAN'T BE WRONG.
SO WHEN MARK HEINRITZ...
HOW YOU GUYS DOING?
AND HIS BROTHER CHRIS...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
TOOK OVER IN '92...
COWBOY REUBEN.
THEY DIDN'T CHANGE MUCH.
WE SEE OURSELVES MORE AS
THE CURATORS OF A PUBLIC DOMAIN
THAN OWNERS
OF THIS PARTICULAR RESTAURANT.
BUT THEY DID BRING IN
CHEF SCOTT BAPTIST...
GOT A WESTERN BURGER.
TO TAKE THINGS UP A NOTCH...
TURKEY PANINI, ONION RING.
LIKE PUTTING SCRATCH-MADE PESTO
ON THIS SINK FAVORITE.
(woman)
THE BUDDAH BASIL PIZZA.
IT'S LIKE YUMMINESS
IN MY MOUTH.
DUDE, I FIND THE STRANGEST
PEOPLE IN THE STRANGEST LOCA--
I SHOULDN'T SAY STRANGE.
THIS IS MY FRATERNITY
BROTHER SCOTT.
A FEW THINGS HAVE CHANGED.
A COUPLE YEARS HAVE GONE BY.
YOU LOOK GREAT.
WELL, THANK YOU.
IT'S BECAUSE I DO PILATES.
WHAT ARE WE INTO, BROTHER?
THIS IS A WALNUT PESTO
AS OPPOSED TO YOUR PINE NUTS
FOR OUR BUDDAH BASIL PIZZA.
PINE NUTS TYPICALLY.
WE START WITH ORGANIC BASIL
THAT WE'RE BRINGING IN
FROM THE FARM JUST
LIKE 20 MILES UP THE ROAD...
DANG IT.
MMM, THAT SMELLS GOOD.
TOASTED WALNUTS...
TEST THESE FOR YOU.
SOME GARLIC CLOVE,
GRATED PARMESAN CHEESE.
WHAT ARE THESE LITTLE CUPS
YOU KEEP POURING OUT OF?
COMPOSTABLE PRODUCTS
THAT WE USE.
I LIKE IT.
SALT-PEPPER MIX,
A BIT OF LEMON JUICE...
ALWAYS NEED SOME ACID.
CRANK THIS,
SOME EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
DO YOU WANT
TO TASTE THIS?
OF COURSE
I WANT TO TASTE THIS.
(coughs) THAT'S AWESOME.
(laughs)
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THAT'S GONNA GO ON A PIZZA?
YES.
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
OUR SESAME HONEY
PIZZA DOUGH.
ALL RIGHT.
TO OUR HONEY POT.
I DID NOT EXPECT THAT YOU
WOULD HAVE YOUR OWN HONEY POT.
SCOTTY THE POOH.
THAT'S TO KEEP
THE HONEY WARM
SO IT COMES OUT
A LITTLE LESS VISCOUS.
THIS IS LOCAL.
YOU HAVE HONEY
ON TAP.
LET'S GO MAKE THIS--
YEAST, WATER...
ROOM TEMP JUST
SO WE BLOOM THAT YEAST.
NOW MIX IN HONEY
AND VEGETABLE OIL.
OIL AND HONEY.
NOW WE'LL PUT THE HONEY
AND THE OIL MIXTURE, YEAST.
THE YEAST IS GONNA
SNACK ON THE HONEY.
NOW HOW LONG WILL THIS BLOOM
BEFORE WE ADD IT TO THE FLOUR?
FIVE OR TEN MINUTES.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE INTO?
MIXING THE PIZZA DOUGH.
LET'S GO.
WHITE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
SALT, SESAME SEEDS, SUGAR.
AND THIS MAKES
A PIZZA?
THIS MAKES
A GREAT PIZZA.
INCORPORATE THAT ALL?
THAT'S RIGHT.
ADD THE YEAST-OIL-
HONEY-WATER COMBO.
THAT'S CORRECT.
MIX, MIX, MIX, MIX, MIX.
THEN YOU'RE GOING
TO TAKE THE GIGANTIC GLOBE,
LET IT PROOF UP
A COUPLE TIMES?
JUST ONCE.
DOWN TO THE PIZZA OVEN?
YES.
WOW, WE'RE LOOKING AT THE FIRST
PIZZA DOUGH SHEETER
THAT WAS EVER MADE.
BRACE FOR IT.
THIS IS CALLED
THE UGLY CRUST.
YOU TAKE IT
RIGHT OUT OF THIS TUB,
CUT IT.
A BIT MORE FLOUR.
SEND IT.
(machine whirring)
(laughs)
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
CUT A LITTLE BIT OFF.
WHAT IS THIS CAVEMAN
PIZZA OPERATION YOU HAVE?
STRETCH IT OUT.
DOCK IT.
TWO SAUCES--PIZZA SAUCE
AND THEN PESTO.
MIX THE TWO TOGETHER.
MMM, I LOVE RED SAUCE
AND PESTO TOGETHER.
SHREDDED MOZZARELLA,
FRESH TOMATOES,
FRESH SPINACH, ROASTED GARLIC,
ARTICHOKE HEARTS,
CHOPPED TOFU...
BRUSHED IT
WITH THE GARLIC OIL,
TOASTED GARLIC
ON THE EDGE.
OKAY.
A LITTLE MORE
OF THAT MOZZ.
THAT'S A MONSTER PIE,
MAN.
JUST A TINY BIT OF PARM.
TAKE THAT OVER TO THE OVEN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU JUST
FAN IT OUT LIKE THAT.
CRIMP IT UP.
AND WE'RE DOING 500 DEGREES,
8 OR 9 MINUTES.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
IT'S HUGE. HOW DO YOU FIT IT
IN A PIZZA BOX?
SEE THE CRUST
ON THIS THING?
GIVE IT A LITTLE
FRESH BASIL.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. NICE AND FRESH
AND WHOLESOME.
MMM.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
PESTO AND MARINARA
GO TOGETHER SO WELL. MMM.
GARLIC AND HONEY--
I DIDN'T KNOW THEY GO TOGETHER.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
THIS UGLY CRUST...
A LITTLE BIT OF HONEY.
MMM--
IS ACTUALLY VERY ENTICING.
NICE JOB, MAN.
GOOD PIE.
THANKS.
BUDDAH BASIL PIZZA.
IT TASTES AMAZING.
THE PESTO AND TOMATO SAUCE
COMES IN.
THE CRUST IS AMAZING.
IT'S A LITTLE SWEET TREAT
FOR THE END.
AND ALL THE FOOD
IS REALLY GOOD.
WE ALWAYS HANG OUT HERE.
IT JUST PERSONIFIES
THE ENTIRE CITY.
'CAUSE THERE ARE PICTURES
OF BOULDER ON EACH TABLE...
THERE YOU GUYS GO.
AND STORIES OF THE SINK
ON EVERY WALL.
THE DRAWINGS HAVE BEEN
ON THE WALLS SINCE THE '60s.
YOU SEE CERTAIN
CHARACTERS AND PEOPLE
THAT WOULD
FREQUENT THE BAR.
AND YOU NEVER KNOW WHO MIGHT
WALK THROUGH THE DOOR.
ROBERT REDFORD
PLAYED BASEBALL AT COLORADO,
WORKED FOR
A FEW MONTHS HERE.
REALLY?
REALLY.
AND YOU CAN STILL
GET THE SAME BURGERS SERVED
WHEN HE WAS ON THE TEAM...
(man) SINK BURGER.
REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
OR A MORE RECENT VERSION.
ONION STRING BURGER.
CRISP ONION STRINGS--
FANTASTIC.
THE GRASS-FED BEEF
MAKES THIS BURGER.
LOOK AT THE BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
NOW HOW BIG OF A PATTY?
1/2 POUND.
80/20?
YES, SIR.
HAND PATTY.
OH, IT'S GONNA
COOK UP NICE.
OKAY
AND THE ONION STRAWS.
THE ONION STRAWS ARE JULIENNE
ONIONS MIXED WITH BUTTERMILK.
THEN WE HAVE
A FLOUR MIXTURE--
CORNMEAL, SALT,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
I LIKE IT.
MIX IT
WITH THE ONIONS.
NICE LITTLE GRIT
TO IT.
OKAY, WHAT DO YOU GOT?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A CHIPOTLE BARBECUE SAUCE
FOR THE MAYONNAISE.
BUTTER AND YELLOW ONION...
A LITTLE GARLIC.
SALT, LET'S GIVE IT
A LITTLE STIR.
TRY AND GET THESE ONIONS
NICE AND SAUTéED.
CAYENNE PEPPER,
BLACK PEPPER.
WE'RE INCORPORATING THESE
NICE, NICE.
YELLOW MUSTARD, KETCHUP.
NOW THE HEAT.
CHIPOTLES IN ADOBO.
YES.
OKAY.
ANOTHER STIR.
THE RED WINE VINEGAR,
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE...
A LITTLE LIQUID SMOKE.
AND SOME BROWN SUGAR
TO KIND OF BALANCE THIS OUT.
I LIKE THAT
PRECISE MEASUREMENT.
SO I WANT TO, LIKE,
THIN IT OUT A BIT.
1/2 A GALLON OF WATER
AND LEMON JUICE.
THAT'S A PASTEURIZED,
FRESH-SQUEEZED?
IT IS.
AND HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA SIMMER?
THIS WILL SIMMER FOR ABOUT
45 MINUTES. NOW I'M GONNA PURéE.
OKAY, SO THE CHIPOTLE SAUCE
WE MADE.
CORRECT.
THAT TASTES GREAT
BY ITSELF.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
CHIPOTLE MAYONNAISE.
OKAY.
MAYONNAISE, CHIPOTLE BARBECUE,
A LITTLE MORE CHIPOTLE POWDER.
AND JUST
A LITTLE MORE HEAT.
GOTTA KICK IT UP.
WAY TO OWN IT.
I WANT TO TASTE THIS.
THE CHIPOTLE POWDER
WAS A NICE KICKER.
ALL RIGHT.
GLOVING UP.
AS ONE SHOULD.
GRASS-FED BURGER,
SALT, PEPPER, A LITTLE GARLIC.
CHARBROIL IT.
GOES ON A FLATTOP.
FRESH SLICED JALAPEÑOS.
NOT COOKED AT ALL?
NO. IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE FLAVOR.
I'M A DEAD MAN
WITH THAT ONE.
CHEDDAR, PROVOLONE,
AND THE MAGIC DOME.
LOCALLY MADE BUN?
YES, ORGANIC SESAME BUN.
NOW THE CHIPOTLE MAYO
AND FINALLY THE ONION STRINGS.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THIS THING.
MMM. OH, BOY.
JALAPEÑO.
OH, THAT'S HOT. MMM.
DUDE, THAT GRASS-FED BEEF,
MMM.
YOU CAN PICK UP THE TRUE,
RICH BEEF FLAVOR. MMM.
THE AMOUNT OF JALAPEÑOS--
ON THE RIDICULOUS SIDE.
(laughs)
THE HIGHLIGHT
OF THIS WHOLE THING
IS THAT BURGER MEAT
IS ON POINT.
GOOD.
MMM. AWESOME JOB, DAWG.
THANKS.
ONION STRING BURGER.
IT'S NICE AND JUICY.
AND THE ONION REALLY JUST
COMPLETES THE WHOLE BITE.
(Scott) BARBECUE PIZZA.
IT'S JUST
A GREAT PLACE.
COWBOY REUBEN UP.
I ALWAYS STICK
WITH WHAT I LOVE,
AND THIS RESTAURANT GIVES ME
WHAT I LOVE.
AND CURATORS
OF THE PUBLIC DOMAIN--
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT'S
GOING ON HERE. NICE JOINT.
THANK YOU.
GOOD TIME.
HEY.
UP NEXT...
CHICKEN SANDWICH,
FARM GREENS.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO CHICAGO...
THIS PLACE DOES IT
REALLY, REALLY WELL.
WHERE IT'S PO'BOYS...
SERIOUSLY, WHERE ARE YOU
GONNA PUT THE SHRIMP?
TO THE MAX...
AND NOW I'VE GOTTA
RELEASE MY JAW.
I'M HERE IN THE BRIDGEPORT
NEIGHBORHOOD OF CHICAGO
ABOUT A MILE AWAY
FROM WHERE THE WHITE SOX PLAY
TO CHECK OUT A PLACE
THAT I HEAR HAS GREAT FOOD
AND A GREAT STORY,
ABOUT A FAMILY OF SIX
THAT LIVED ABOVE A BAR
THAT THEY EVENTUALLY TURNED
INTO THEIR OWN RESTAURANT
THAT'S SERVING ORGANIC,
FARM-TO-TABLE COMFORT FOOD.
THIS IS NANA.
CHICKEN SANDWICH,
FARM GREENS.
IT'S JUST PHENOMENAL.
WE HAVE THE SHRIMP
AND OYSTER PO'BOY.
TODAY, I'M HAVING
THE DUCK BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
OH, I LOVE NANA'S.
AND THERE REALLY IS A NANA...
I NAMED IT
AFTER MY MOM.
MEXICAN-BORN MARIA SOLIS...
HI, LADIES.
WHOSE 4 KIDS
OPENED THIS JOINT IN 2009.
THAT WOULD BE OMAR,
CHRISTIAN...
BREAKFAST BURRITO.
MARCO, AND MICHELLE.
CHILAQUILES.
BASICALLY, ALL WE'VE DONE
IS TAKEN A LOT OF THESE
COMFORT DISHES INSPIRED
BY MOM'S HOME COOKING...
AND GAVE THE RECIPES
TO HIGH-END CHEF GUY MEIKLE.
HUEVOS RANCHERO.
HE IS ON THE PAR WITH ALL
THE GREAT CHEFS IN TOWN.
AND NOW HE'S PUTTING
THE NANA SPIN ON COMFORT FOOD,
LIKE THIS TOP SELLER.
NANADICT.
THE WHAT?
THE NANADICT.
VARIATION ON EGGS BENEDICT
WITH CHORIZO.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CHORIZO OURSELVES.
CORRECT.
I DIG THIS. OKAY, SO WE
REHYDRATE THE ANCHOS.
YEP.
SO YOU PULL SEEDS
AND STEMS NOW?
MM-HMM.
THERE WE GO. HIT IT
WITH THE WATER,
AND JUST LET 'EM STEEP THERE
FOR WHAT?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES, JUST TILL
THEY GET NICE AND SOFT.
YEP, THEY'RE STEEPED. YOU'RE
GONNA PURéE 'EM RIGHT NOW.
SO NOW THAT'S PURéED.
RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE MAKING
THE CURE.
FRESH GARLIC,
FRESH THYME, CINNAMON...
THAT'S A MESS OF CINNAMON.
GROUND CLOVES, CAYENNE,
DRY OREGANO,
SMOKED SWEET PAPRIKA.
SO ALL IN.
OUR ANCHO PURéE.
TO THE STOVE.
SO WE COOK OFF THE SPICES
FOR TEN MINUTES.
GOT IT.
NEED TO CHILL IT DOWN
IN AN ICE BATH.
'CAUSE WE CAN'T MIX THE WARM
PRODUCT INTO THE COLD.
GROUND PORK.
WHERE'S THIS COMING FROM?
THIS IS FROM GUNTHORP FARMS.
ALL RIGHT. ALL OF THAT IN.
MM-HMM.
OKAY, WE'LL LET THIS CURE UP
FOR ABOUT A WEEK?
YEP.
SO YOU'RE CONSTANTLY
MAKING THIS.
YEAH.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE JUST GONNA SAUTé IT,
OLIVE OIL.
WE ADD A SPLASH
OF WHITE WINE VINEGAR.
COOL.
THAT'S IT.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
MAKING POBLANO CREAM SAUCE--
FRESH POBLANOS ROASTED,
2 QUARTS
OF HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM.
THE WHOLE MILK ALSO?
YEP.
DOCTOR.
SCALPEL.
HOW ABOUT TOMATILLOS?
TOMATILLOS--THAT'LL WORK.
I DIDN'T HAVE ANY SCALPEL.
TOMATILLOS.
S AND P.
A LITTLE BIT NOW,
LITTLE BIT AT THE END.
OKAY, SO WE LET THIS COME UP
TO A BOIL?
YEP. SO NOW
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR SOUR CREAM, CILANTRO,
AND THEN SALT AND PEPPER.
HIT IT
WITH THE IMMERSION BLENDER.
MIX IT ALL UP,
AND THAT'S IT.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
PUPUSAS.
I SEE THE MASA,
HARINA DE MAIZ.
YEP.
THAT'S CORN FLOUR.
THIS IS A CHEESE PUPUSA?
YEP, CHEESE PUPUSA, RAW MILK,
JACK CHEESE, OLIVE OIL,
WATER.
OKAY.
LITTLE BIT OF KOSHER SALT.
OKAY, SO YOU MIX
THE PUPUSA THOROUGHLY.
A LITTLE EXTRA SALT.
BLACK PEPPER.
SO NOW YOU FORM IT OUT.
2-OUNCE BALL.
NOW YOU HIT THE MOLD?
YEP.
THERE WE GO.
DROP THE PUPUSAS AND HOME FRIES
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
OKAY.
TWO DEEP-FRIED PUPUSAS, HOME
FRIES, HOUSE-MADE CHORIZO.
OF COURSE.
TWO POACHED EGGS.
HERE EGGY, EGGY, EGGY.
POBLANO CREAM SAUCE,
WILD ARUGULA AND SPINACH
WITH ORANGE VINAIGRETTE.
FIRST, I GOT TO JUST TRY
THIS CHORIZO BY ITSELF.
MMM, TONS OF FLAVOR. MMM.
THE CRUNCH AND THE TEXTURE
OF THE PUPUSA--
MMM--ROCK STAR DISH.
I KNEW THIS GUY
WAS GONNA BE ABLE TO DO IT
WITH A NAME LIKE GUY.
COME ON.
THE NANADICT--
IT'S FANTASTIC.
IT'S THE BEST CHORIZO
I THINK I'VE EVER HAD.
THEIR FOOD
JUST SPEAKS FOR ITSELF.
ORGANIC AND LOCAL
SUSTAINABLE FOOD
WAS SOMETHING THAT WE WANTED
TO BE A PART OF.
CHICKEN SANDWICH, FARM GREENS.
THIS PLACE DOES IT
REALLY, REALLY WELL.
FROM FRESH POULTRY...
(Christian) BEAUTIFUL
DUCK BREAST PROSCIUTTO.
TO GARDEN PRODUCE...
OUR HOUSE-MADE GIARDINIERA,
WHICH IS A LOT
OF LOCAL VEGETABLES.
THAT TOPS THEIR TAKE
ON THIS NEW ORLEANS CLASSIC.
SHRIMP AND OYSTER PO'BOY.
FANTASTIC.
TOOK THE BASIC PO'BOY
AND JUST TOOK LITTLE TWIST,
ENOUGH TO MAKE IT DIFFERENT
THAN THE OTHER PO'BOYS
THAT ARE IN THE CITY.
OKAY, NEXT UP.
WE'RE MAKING OUR GIARDINIERA
FOR OUR PO'BOY.
DO IT.
SALT AND SUGAR, WATER.
I SEE VINEGAR.
BAY LEAF, CHILE de ARBOL,
BLACK PEPPERCORN, AND CORIANDER.
SIMMER 30 MINUTES?
YEAH, JUST TILL THE SALT
AND SUGAR DISSOLVES.
LET IT SOAK UP SOME OF
THE FLAVOR OUT OF THE SPICES.
AND THEN...
WE NEED TO MAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF GIARDINIERA
FOR OUR TOPPING,
DICED CARROTS.
(whistles)
LIKE CONFETTI, AY.
GREEN PEPPER, CELERY,
WHITE ONION, ORANGE PEPPER.
CAULIFLOWER,
ONE OF THE KEY COMPONENTS
TO A GOOD GIARDINIERA.
SHAVED GARLIC,
HOT PICKLING MIXTURE.
WARM, SO IT JUST KIND OF STEEPS
THOSE VEGGIES A LITTLE BIT.
AS IT'S COOLING, WE'LL ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF SLICED RADISH
AND SHAVED JALAPEÑO
FOR THE EXTRA KICK.
(whistles)
YEAH, I LIKE TO LET IT SIT
FOR TWO OR THREE DAYS
AND LET ALL THE FLAVORS
REALLY MARRY IN.
AND THIS IS GONNA GO ON TOP OF
THE OYSTER AND SHRIMP PO'BOY.
CORRECT.
NICE. WHAT'S UP NEXT?
WE'RE MARINATING
OUR SHRIMP AND OYSTERS,
PEELED AND DEVEINED SHRIMP,
CHILE de ARBOL.
USED A LOT IN MEXICAN COOKING,
REALLY GREAT CHILI FLAVOR.
FRESH GROUND GARLIC, CHOPPED
PARSLEY, EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
WE'RE ALL ABOUT THE LAYERING
OF FLAVORS.
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
OUR SHUCKED OYSTERS.
SOAK IT IN BUTTERMILK
FOR TWO DAYS.
NEXT UP.
SAUCE GRIBICHE,
SO WE HAVE TO--
SAUCE GRIBICHE?
GRIBICHE. EGG YOLKS...
THERE WE GO.
WHOLE GRAIN MUSTARD,
GARLIC CONFIT...
ROASTED GARLIC. YOU JUST LIKE
FANCY-DANCY WORDS.
CANOLA OIL...
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE A LITTLE
MAYO. EMULSIFY THAT IN.
FRESH LEMON JUICE
JUST TO THIN IT BACK OUT.
THIS IS ALL
JUST FOR THE PO'BOY?
YEAH.
OKAY.
MIXING BOWL.
NICE, TIGHT.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
SMASH OUR HARD-COOKED EGG YOLKS
AND WHITES.
HOUSE-MADE PICKLE.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
CAPTAIN STUBING.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT ANYBODY GOT
EXCALIBUR OUT OF THE ROCK.
GETTING THICKLE
WITH THE PICKLE.
CAPER BERRY,
CHOPPED RED ONION,
TARRAGON, CHIVES,
CHOPPED PARSLEY.
MIXY MIX.
THERE YOU GO.
NEXT STEP.
CAJUN DREDGE
FOR OUR FIVE OYSTERS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
FRY 'EM IN?
DEEP FRYER.
JUST UNTIL THEY PUT UP A CRISP.
LEAVE 'EM TENDER IN THE CENTER.
FEW GRILLED SHRIMP.
THAT'S A LOT
OF SEAFOOD, BROTHER.
WANT ME TO FLIP
THE SHRIMP, BOSS?
SURE.
FINALLY, WE CAN MAKE
THE SANDWICH?
YES. EVERYTHING'S COMING
TO A CULMINATION.
I'M TELLING YOU. I ALMOST
WITHERED AWAY TO NOTHING.
DON'T SAY IT.
GRIBICHE.
MMM.
OYSTERS.
SERIOUSLY, WHERE ARE YOU
GONNA PUT THE SHRIMP?
ARUGULA, SLICED TOMATO,
GIARDINIERA.
MMM.
GRILLED SHRIMP RIGHT ON THERE,
AND THERE YOU GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND NOW I'VE GOT TO RELEASE
MY JAW. MMM.
FULL OF FLAVOR,
A LOT OF CRUNCH.
THE GIARDINIERA
GIVES THAT NICE CONTRAST
WITH THE CUT
AND THE VINEGAR.
AND THE GRIBICHE IS SMOOTH,
NICE LITTLE BIT OF FAT.
FUHGEDDABOUDIT. MMM.
NICE JOB.
(man) SHRIMP AND OYSTER PO'BOY.
THIS RIVALS ANYTHING
I'VE HAD DOWN IN LOUISIANA
DOWN TO NEW ORLEANS.
IF YOU'RE WITHIN A COUPLE
HUNDRED MILES OF CHICAGO,
I WOULD RECOMMEND COMING BY
AND TRYING THIS.
WHEN WE COME BACK TO NANA'S
IN CHICAGO ON THE SOUTH SIDE,
MY BUDDY GUY HERE IS GONNA
ROCK IT OUT WITH A DUCK CONFIT.
DUCK CONFIT BISCUITS
AND GRAVY.
I DON'T KNOW
IF I CAN HANDLE IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO HERE'S TRIPLE "D"
IN CHICAGO ON THE SOUTH SIDE
RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM THE BALLPARK
AT A JOINT CALLED NANA'S
HANGING OUT WITH A GUY
NAMED GUY.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME...
DUCK CONFIT.
DUCK CONFIT FOR THE...
DUCK CONFIT
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
YOU SEE IT EVERY DAY. ALL RIGHT,
BROTHER, HOW WE DOING IT?
KOSHER SALT, NATURAL CANE
JUICE-EVAPORATED SUGAR.
SO THEY SQUEEZED THE JUICE
OUT OF THE CANE.
THEY ROLL IT THROUGH.
THEY LAY IT OUT.
THEY LET IT
NATURALLY EVAPORATE,
AND THESE ARE THE CRYSTALS
THAT ARE LEFT WITH.
RIGHT.
JUNIPER BERRIES, CORIANDER.
BLACK PEPPER?
YEP. MIX ALL
OF OUR SPICES UP.
I READ A LOT IN YOUR FUTURE.
YOU WILL BE ON TV SHOW.
NO, COOKING SHOW.
OKAY, SO WE HAVE
OUR DUCK LEGS.
ALL FREE-RANGE?
YEP.
(exhales deeply)
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA LAYER IT
IN THE PAN TO CURE.
SALT AND SUGAR MIXTURE,
FRESH THYME,
LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
DUCK LEGS.
SO YOU PACK IT IN
NICE AND TIGHT.
CORRECT.
SO THIS IS GONNA PULL
SOME OF THE MOISTURE OUT.
RIGHT.
AND HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
THREE DAYS.
THEN WE'LL TAKE IT OUT,
RINSE IT ALL OFF.
YES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GET
INTO THE CONFIT PROCESS.
MORE OF THE FRESH THYME.
DUCK FAT.
YOU SHOULD SMELL IT
RIGHT NOW.
THIS IS GONNA GO OVEN 250
4 HOURS?
YEP.
THAT'S HOT.
THAT'S REAL HOT.
WATCH, MOM. HE'S GONNA TASTE IT.
HE'S GONNA TASTE IT.
I'M NOT TASTING IT
RIGHT NOW.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL TASTE
JUST A LITTLE PIECE.
MMM. LIKE BUTTER, DUDE.
LET IT COOL. SHRED IT.
THERE YOU GO.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE JUST GONNA GET
OUR BISCUITS MIXED.
ORGANIC FLOUR,
BAKING POWDER, SALT...
COLD CUBED BUTTER.
5-YEAR AGED CHEDDAR.
OF COURSE IT IS.
GOOD CHEDDAR.
BREAK IT UP
INTO NICE PEA-SIZE CLUMPS,
THREE EGGS.
YOU'RE LEAVING THE BUTTER
IN CHUNKS THAT BIG?
YEAH.
YOU ARE GANGSTER.
QUART AND 1/2
OF BUTTERMILK.
JUST INCORPORATING IT ENOUGH
TO WHERE EVERYTHING'S WET.
NEED A LITTLE FLOUR?
YEP.
LOOKING GOOD. JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF BENCH FLOUR ON THAT
JUST TO WORK THIS OUT.
USUALLY ROLL IT OUT
TO AN INCH.
LOOK AT THOSE MONDO-SIZE CHUNKS
OF BUTTER IN THERE.
CUT THEM INTO SQUARES.
THE EXCALIBUR 9000.
LOADED WITH CHEESE, LOADED
WITH BUTTER ONTO A BAKING TRAY.
GONNA BRUSH 'EM WITH ANYTHING
ON TOP?
YEP, LITTLE BIT
OF AGAVE HONEY.
BAKE THESE OFF
15 MINUTES AT 375?
YEAH.
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
OUR GARNISH FOR THE DUCK CONFIT
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
OKAY.
CARROTS, WHITE TURNIP,
CELERY ROOT, PARSNIPS...
ALL MY ROOT
VEGGIE FAVORITES.
OLIVE OIL...
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL
ON THAT.
KOSHER SALT, PEPPER,
CHOPPED FRESH THYME.
CAPTAIN ORGANIC.
WE'RE GONNA COOK 'EM DOWN.
350 FOR 25--
25 MINUTES.
YEP.
NOW WE'RE MAKING THE--
DUCK FAT GRAVY.
WE'RE GONNA USE A LITTLE BIT
OF DUCK FAT.
'CAUSE WE HAVE A DUCK FAT WELL
ON THE BACK THAT WE PUMP.
A.P. FLOUR.
MAKING A NICE LITTLE ROUX.
BRING IT UP
TO A BLOND COLOR.
SMELL THAT DUCK FAT
FROM HERE.
HOT DUCK STOCK.
TOO MANY DUCKS IN THE POND.
NOW WE SEASON IT.
LITTLE MEXICAN HOT SAUCE,
WORCESTERSHIRE.
SALT, LITTLE BIT OF PEPPER,
WHITE WINE VINEGAR.
(whistles)
NOW IT'S TIME
FOR BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
MAKE OUR LITTLE RAGOUT, OLIVE
OIL, ROASTED ROOT VEGETABLES.
CONFIT CIPOLLINI ONION,
DUCK CONFIT.
MMM.
TWO BISCUITS,
THE DUCK FAT GRAVY....
MMM.
DUCK CONFIT HASH,
AND TWO EGGS YOUR WAY.
TWO EGGS MY WAY.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
MMM. I MEAN, DUCK IS SO RICH,
SAVORY BISCUIT.
YOU DEFINITELY PICK UP THAT
CHEDDAR RIGHT OFF THE BAT. MMM.
IT HAS SUCH RICHNESS
AND DEPTH
AND TEXTURAL DIFFERENCES.
THE ROOT VEGGIES, IN MY
OPINION--THAT'S THE KICKER. MMM.
YOU COULD EAT THAT MORNING,
NOON, AND NIGHT.
YOU GOT TO GIVE THIS A SHOT.
MMM. PRIME TIME.
DUCK BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
IT'S UNREAL,
ABSOLUTELY DELECTABLE.
(woman) THE BISCUITS ARE REALLY
BUTTERY. GRAVY'S REALLY CREAMY.
GRILLED BURGER.
IT'S HOME-STYLE COOKING
THAT IS WORTH LEAVING HOME FOR.
I LIKE COMING HERE.
THIS IS PERFECT FOR ME.
WHAT YOU HAVE GOING ON IN HERE
IS WHAT EVERYBODY REALLY WANTS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT. THANK YOU.
NANA, THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
THANKS.
NEXT STOP...
MEAT LOAF AND MASHED MEDLEY.
WE'RE HEADING
TO NORFOLK, VIRGINIA...
YOU CAN'T GET BETTER
LOCAL-GROWN FOOD.
TO BANG OUT...
YEAH.
SOME MEAT LOAF.
THAT'S HOW YOU'RE
GONNA ROAST IT?
YEAH, BABY.
WOW.
AS A CHEF, I'M A BIG FAN
OF ORGANICS AND FARM-TO-TABLE,
AND ONE OF THE PLACES
YOU CAN FIND THOSE GREAT FOODS
IS AT A FARMERS' MARKET,
BUT THE QUESTION IS,
WHAT IS
"DINER'S, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
DOING AT THE FIVE POINTS
COMMUNITY FARMERS' MARKET
IN NORFOLK, VIRGINIA?
WELL, WE'RE HERE TO CHECK OUT
A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S USING FRESH PRODUCT
FROM THE MARKET
IN THEIR MENU AT THE MARKET.
THIS IS GET FRESH CAFE.
APPLEWOOD SMOKED RIBS.
I LOVE TO SHOP AT THE FARMERS'
MARKET AND COME TO THE CAFE.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
BRUNSWICK STEW.
THE LOCAL FARMERS COME IN,
DROP OFF THEIR FOOD.
CAN I GET A COUPLE POUNDS
OF YOUR GROUND BEEF?
THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
I'M EATING IT AT THE CAFE.
EXACTLY WHAT MANAGER NIC RENZ
WAS LOOKING FOR...
MEAT LOAF'S DONE.
AFTER YEARS IN THE CORPORATE
RESTAURANT BIZ.
GREEN ALTERNATIVES,
SUSTAINABILITY,
ALL THE ASPECTS OF THIS LITTLE
MARKET--IT WAS JUST FOR ME.
NOW HE'S DOING WHAT HE LOVES...
CAN I GET A DOZEN
OF YOUR FABULOUS EGGS, PLEASE?
YES.
BY THE RULES HE BELIEVES IN.
HEALTHY, SUSTAINABLE,
AFFORDABLE, AND IT'S TASTY.
(Nic) PORK BARBECUE PLATE.
AMAZING
PULLED PORK BARBECUE.
CRAB CAKE SANDWICH.
DELICIOUS, FRESH
LUMP CRABMEAT.
MEAT LOAF AND MASHED MEDLEY.
WHEN THE MEAT
IS FRESH AND LOCAL,
YOU REALLY DO TASTE
THE DIFFERENCE.
WE'LL MAKE A MEAT LOAF.
WE START
WITH GRASS-FED BEEF.
THE FARMER IS ABOUT
100 MILES FROM HERE.
CAN'T BEAT THE FARM-TO-TABLE
ON THAT, BABY.
RED AND GREEN
BELL PEPPERS, CELERY,
CHOPPED ONIONS,
GRANULATED GARLIC...
OKAY.
SALT, PEPPER,
ITALIAN SEASONING.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
YOU WRITING THIS DOWN?
YEAH. NO, I GOT IT.
ALL RIGHT. PAPRIKA,
CRUSHED GARLIC,
FRESH ROSEMARY,
AND FRESH SAGE.
I LIKE THE WAY
THIS IS ROLLING.
WORCESTERSHIRE
AND MOLASSES.
OOH. DON'T SEE THAT
IN MEAT LOAF VERY OFTEN.
NO. THAT'S MY TRICK.
THIS IS MY HOMEMADE
SPAGHETTI SAUCE
AND LOCAL FRESH EGGS.
OH, LOOK AT HOW ORANGE
THOSE YOLKS ARE.
ADD THOSE TO BIND THAT UP
AND BREAD.
MIX ALL THAT UP.
JUST JUMP RIGHT IN THERE.
THIS IS THE FUN PART.
ALL RIGHT.
LITTLE OIL IN THE PAN.
WANT TO MAKE SURE TO PACK IT.
SO IT WILL COOK EVENLY.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
OH, YOU'RE GONNA...
YEAH.
THAT'S HOW
YOU'RE GONNA ROAST IT?
YEAH, BABY.
WOW, CRUNCH-A-LICIOUS.
I'M GONNA--
KNOCK OUT THE OTHER THREE?
YEAH. AND THE LAST STEP HERE
IS THE MARINARA SAUCE
AND DRIED ROSEMARY.
SPRINKLE THAT ALL OVER.
OKAY.
PERFECT. SO THOSE ARE READY
FOR THE OVEN.
350 FOR AN HOUR?
FOR AN HOUR.
LET'S GET ROLLING.
NEXT OFF
IS MY MASHED MEDLEY.
I'M STARTING OFF WITH PARSNIPS
AND SOME TURNIPS
FROM LOCAL FARMERS
AND SOME POTATOES.
SO WE'RE GONNA
LET THIS GO.
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHTY.
OKAY. THE MASH IS READY.
YEP. ADD SOME BUTTER,
GARLIC, ROSEMARY,
PEPPER, GARLIC GRANULES,
SOME CREAM.
CHICKEN STOCK?
CHICKEN BROTH. YEAH. WE'LL
MASH THESE UP REALLY GOOD.
OKAY. ALL MASHED UP.
TIME TO GRAB THE MEAT LOAF.
YEAH.
CRUSTED UP NICE.
ALL RIGHT.
LET IT COOL. SLICE IT.
GET SOME OF THIS MASHED MEDLEY
FOR YOU.
THE MEAT LOAF
AND HOMEMADE GRAVY,
AND THAT'S READY
FOR YOU TO EAT UP.
OKAY.
HMM. DELICIOUS MEAT LOAF.
NICE TEXTURE, NICE CRUST TO IT,
LITTLE SWEETNESS COMING
FROM THAT TOMATO SAUCE,
THE MASH, REALLY CREAMY,
OVER-THE-TOP.
KNOCK IT OUT, MAN.
WELL, THANK YOU, MAN.
VERY GOOD,
VERY, VERY GOOD.
MEAT LOAF READY TO WALK.
IT MUST MELTS IN MY MOUTH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BARBECUE PLATE.
(woman) YOU CAN'T GET BETTER
LOCAL-GROWN FOOD.
IT'S LIKE BEING AT HOME.
I GOT TO TELL YOU,
YOU'RE DOING A GREAT JOB.
GOOD TIME, MAN.
HEY, THANK YOU.
GREAT GUY, GREAT PLACE.
YOU GOT TO COME CHECK THIS OUT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
ALL THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU CAN SEE
THAT I WAS WADDLING INTO IT.