I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I'M ONLY INTO IT
ABOUT TEN SECONDS AND I'M TIRED.
YOU CAN ONLY GET IT HERE...
BARBEQUE PORK,
SCRAMBLED EGGS.
IT'S A CRAZY MIXTURE.
IN SAN FRANCISCO...
TWO MINUTES
ON THE SLOPPY JOJO.
THE COFFEE SHOP...
EVERY SINGLE PLATE
IS DELICIOUS.
KICKING OUT
KIMCHI BURRITOS...
MMM, THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
AND A TOP CHOP.
MMM.
IN INDIANAPOLIS...
(woman) CHIPOTLE CHICKEN TAMALE.
THE LOCAL JOINT...
THIS IS BEST MEXICAN FOOD
I'VE EVER HAD.
CRANKING OUT HANDMADE TAMALES
FOR DINNER...
VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT'S AWESOME.
AND DESSERT.
PINEAPPLE
AND RAISIN TAMALES.
MMM, WOW.
AND IN CHICAGO...
FALUMOU WITH KINGFISH.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
THE FOOD HERE IS AMAZING.
WHERE A TASTE OF BACK HOME...
HERBS AND SPICES
THAT WE USE IN BELIZE.
MEANS FISH STEW...
DELICIOUS.
AND MORE.
THESE ARE SALTED PIGTAILS.
OH, GOOD 'CAUSE I JUST DO NOT
ENJOY THE UNSALTED ONES.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
YOU GOT TO DIG TRIPLE "D"
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA,
ESPECIALLY WHEN I'M JUST
THREE BLOCKS FROM AT&T PARK
WHERE THE SAN FRANCISCO GIANTS
PLAY.
I CRUISE THROUGH THIS AREA
QUITE A BIT,
AND THIS FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
DIDN'T COME UP ON MY RADAR.
IT'S A COFFEE SHOP.
A COFFEE SHOP'S WHAT YOU CALL
A DINER ON THE WEST COAST.
BUT NOT JUST ANY
COFFEE SHOP,
IT'S ONE THAT'S SPIKED
WITH ASIAN FUSION.
THIS IS HRD COFFEE SHOP.
SWEET CHILI FRIED
PORK CHOPS!
I LOVE THE FOOD HERE.
MONGOLIAN CHEESESTEAK.
IT'S ONE OF GREATEST THINGS
I'VE EVER HAD.
SPICY PORK TACOS.
IT'S A CRAZY MIXTURE.
BARBECUE PORK,
SCRAMBLED EGGS.
ASIAN FUSION,
AMERICAN DINER.
SLOPPY JOJO!
HOW CAN THEY DO THAT?
(laughs) EASILY.
ALL RIGHT, THERE WE GO.
I'M CHINESE.
YOU'RE CHINESE.
JOJO'S KOREAN.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU?
THAT'D BE JOJO BANKS.
MORE SPICY PORK.
WHO PARTNERED UP WITH HER PAL
DAVID YEUNG...
HOW LONG'S THE LINE?
WHEN HE DECIDED TO BUY
HIS UNCLE'S COFFEE SHOP.
WE WANTED TO MAKE A MENU
THAT KIND OF COMBINED
ALL FLAVORS THAT WE LIKE TO EAT.
WHAT DO PEOPLE SAY
WHEN THEY WALK IN
AND THEN FIND
KIMCHI FRIED RICE BURRITO?
THEY JUST SCRATCH THEIR HEADS
LIKE YOU DO.
SPICY PORK KIMCHI BURRITO.
OH, YEAH,
THEY ALSO ORDER IT.
KOREAN BARBEQUE IN A BURRITO--
TWO BEST FOODS SMASHED TOGETHER.
YOU PUT KIMCHI ON ANYTHING,
AND IT'S JUST AWESOME.
KIMCHI INTO A BURRITO.
YES.
FIRST THING WE DO
IS WE TAKE NAPA CABBAGE.
CUT IN QUARTERS.
AFTER THIS, KOREAN SEA SALT.
SO THIS WILL PULL
ALL THE MOISTURE OUT.
HOW LONG IS IT JUST GONNA SIT
WITH THE SALT ON IT?
OVERNIGHT.
WE RINSE IT
AND THEN MAKE A SAUCE FOR IT.
GIVE IT TO ME.
SWEET RICE FLOUR. WE'RE GONNA
PUT A LITTLE WATER IN THERE.
NOW WE MIX IT UP.
THIS IS JUST THE BINDING AGENT?
BINDING AGENT.
RED CRUSHED PEPPER.
ALL OF THAT?
(whistles)
ALL OF THAT, OKAY?
KOREAN ANCHOVIES,
ANCHOVY SAUCE.
WE GOT SOME SUGAR,
GET THE NICE PASTE IN THERE.
LEEKS.
JULIENNED LEEKS, SLICED DAIKON.
AND THEN WE GOT SOME CARROTS.
SMELL THE FLAVORS COMING OUT?
HOW PUNGENT IT IS?
YEAH.
THIS IS SERIOUSLY SOME OF THE
STUFF I LOVE MORE THAN ANYTHING.
RUB EVERYTHING INSIDE
REALLY, REALLY WELL.
PUT THIS IN HERE,
LET IT FERMENT.
AND HOW LONG
DOES A KIMCHI FERMENT?
A DAY.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
KOREAN SPICY PORK SAUCE.
CHOPPED ONIONS,
CHOPPED GINGER, GARLIC.
PUT A LITTLE WATER IN THERE,
KIWI.
THAT LITTLE BIT OF KIWI
MAKES A DIFFERENCE?
YES.
PUT IN THIS MUCH GARLIC
AND THIS MUCH GINGER
(high-pitched)
AND THIS MUCH KIWI.
THEN WE'RE GONNA BLEND IT.
WE'RE GONNA BREAK IT
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
(normal voice) REALLY?
YEAH, THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
ALL THIS STUFF IN THERE.
SUGAR, SOY SAUCE,
KOREAN BEAN PASTE.
I GOT TO TRY THIS.
THAT'S AWESOME!
(laughs)
A LITTLE SWEET SPICY MISO.
LIKE KOREAN PEANUT BUTTER.
(laughs)
KOREAN RED PEPPER FLAKES.
IS THAT HOT?
IT'S VERY HOT.
OKAY.
OKAY. (laughs)
AND THEN WE'LL MIX IT AGAIN.
THIS IS WHAT THE PORK
GETS MARINATED IN.
EXACTLY.
THAT IS AWESOME.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE PORK BUTT.
THE REGULAR OLD PORK BUTT.
SLICE IT THIN.
NOW WE TAKE OUR SLICED PORK.
GOT IT.
YOU GET THAT MARINATING.
IT'S GONNA SOAK UP
THE MARINADE.
UH-HUH.
MARINADE IS THE BOMB.
FOR HOW LONG WILL IT MARINATE?
FOR AT LEAST A DAY.
FIRE IT UP.
SO WE GOT THE SPICY PORK.
WE'LL SEAR A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE CARAMELIZATION
ON THE OUTSIDE, YEAH.
PUT A LITTLE
SESAME OIL IN THERE.
GOT IT.
KIMCHI, WE'RE GONNA CHOP IT UP
AND MIX IT ALL IN THERE.
ALL THE FLAVORS COMING OUT.
SO GOOD.
JASMINE RICE--THIS IS THE SAUCE
WE MADE TO FLAVOR THE RICE.
LOT OF WORK
FOR A BURRITO, BRO.
EXACTLY.
AND THEN SCALLIONS,
GIVE US SOME NICE COLOR.
TAKE THE TORTILLA SHELL,
GET THAT NICE AND HEATED UP.
THE WHOLE MIXTURE,
RIGHT THERE.
LOOK AT THIS.
MUNG BEANS.
LOVE THEM.
JULIENNED CUCUMBERS,
LITTLE BIT OF HOT SAUCE,
SOUR CREAM.
THIS I DON'T GET.
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF NORI.
THIS IS THE ODDEST BURRITO
I'VE EVER SEEN.
ROLL THAT UP RIGHT THERE,
PARCHMENT PAPER.
I'LL EAT RIGHT THROUGH
THE PARCHMENT PAPER.
AND THEN WE'LL WRAP IN FOIL
TO KEEP IT NICE AND HOT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, BROTHER.
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE KIMCHI, A LITTLE BIT SOUR,
LITTLE BIT SPICY.
THE MEAT'S GOT TONS OF FLAVOR,
A LITTLE CHEW.
AND THE MUNG BEAN--MMM, DUDE,
THAT IS SERIOUSLY THE BOMB.
NICE JOB,
ROCKED IT OUT.
THANKS, BRO.
SPICY PORK KIMCHI BURRITO.
THE KIMCHI
REALLY COMES THROUGH.
SPICY,
GIVES A LITTLE TANG.
(Jojo) HERE YOU GO.
WITH A LITTLE ZING,
A LITTLE ZANG, IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
SPICY PORK TACOS!
EVERY SINGLE PLATE
IS DELICIOUS.
SLOPPY JOJO!
AND YOU GET A HUGE PORTION.
BARBEQUE PORK, SCRAMBLED EGGS.
BUT WHAT TRIPS ME OUT
EVEN MORE IS THE PRICE.
A FULL MEAL...
SPICY PORK CHOW FUN UP!
FOR UNDER 8 BUCKS...
CAN'T BE BEAT.
FROM CHINESE YELLOW
CURRY CHICKEN...
IT'S NICE AND CREAMY.
TO KOREAN BEEF SHORT RIBS...
UP IN 30 SECONDS,
OKAY?
AND CHECK OUT
THE PORK CHOP VALUE MEAL.
SWEET CHILI FRIED PORK CHOPS
FOR YOU!
TWO PORK CHOPS WITH
A MOUND OF FRENCH FRIES.
THIS IS JUST SOMETHING ELSE.
THEY'VE GOT THE PERFECT SAUCE
FOR IT.
IT'S REALLY TASTY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MARINADE
FOR THE SWEET CHILI
FRIED PORK CHOPS.
GOT IT.
WE GOT GINGER, ONIONS,
GARLIC AND THEN...
OF COURSE.
A LITTLE BIT OF KIWI.
LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
OH, IT SMELLS AWESOME.
ADD SOME SOY SAUCE,
SUGAR, WHISK.
WE'LL TAKE THE PORK CHOPS,
MARINADE ALL OVER IT.
THIS IS THE SUPER MARINADE.
I CAN JUST SMELL IT.
THIS IS MY KIND OF FOOD.
HOW LONG WILL THIS MARINATE?
ANOTHER DAY.
NOW WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE FINISHING
SAUCE FOR THE MARINADE.
PUT A LITTLE HONEY IN THERE,
WHITE VINEGAR,
SESAME OIL IN THERE,
SESAME SEEDS.
WE'RE DEEP-FRYING
THE PORK CHOPS.
THIS IS THE SAUCE
THAT'S GONNA GET PUT ON THERE?
EXACTLY.
THE PORK CHOPS MARINATED, WE
DUST IT WITH SIMPLE CORNSTARCH
AND ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
SO YOU GET
THAT EXTRA LITTLE CRUNCH.
THIS GOES IN THE FRYER.
NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
TAKE THE SAUCE,
POUR ALL OVER IT.
WE'RE STILL COOKING THIS?
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON THE FLAT GRILL.
AND A LITTLE BIT
MORE SAUCE.
GOT YOU.
GET THE FRENCH FRIES
ON THERE.
FRENCH FRIES?!
OF COURSE. PORK CHOPS
GO RIGHT ON TOP OF THAT.
OH, MY GOSH.
MMM.
THAT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE CRUNCHINESS OF THE FRIES
SOAKING UP THE SAUCE.
WHEN YOU COOK IT DOWN THERE
IN THE FRYER,
KIND OF RENDERS
SOME OF THE FAT OUT
SO YOU'RE LEFT WITH THE MEAT.
WHERE DOES THIS COME FROM?
MORE THE KOREAN SIDE.
REALLY?
IT HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF AMERICAN STYLE, TOO,
BECAUSE YOU GOT
THE FRIED PORK CHOPS.
NO WONDER THE GIANTS WON
THE WORLD SERIES.
YOU'RE THREE BLOCKS
AWAY FROM THEM. NAILED IT.
SWEET CHILI PORK CHOPS.
IT'S THE PERFECT MIXTURE
OF SWEET AND SPICY.
THEY FRY IT JUST RIGHT.
AND THEN FRIES ON THE SIDE.
IT GIVES IT THAT AMERICAN TWIST.
TWO MINUTES ON THE SLOPPY JOJO,
OKAY?
I DON'T FIND THIS KIND OF FOOD
ANYWHERE ELSE.
KIMCHI BURRITO UP!
ONE OF THOSE LITTLE GREAT PLACES
WHERE THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
(man) LOOKS REALLY GOOD.
(Jojo) OH, YOU LIKE IT?
IT IS A COOL SPOT.
I WILL BE BACK,
PLEASE DON'T CLOSE EARLY.
UP NEXT...
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
WE'RE HEADING
TO INDIANAPOLIS...
BEEF AND RED SAUCE TAMALE.
MMM.
WHERE TAMALES
MEET APPLE PIE.
APPLE PECAN, THEY'RE GREAT.
YOU DON'T GET THOSE ANYWHERE.
I'M HERE IN INDIANAPOLIS
JUST A COUPLE MILES
FROM THE FAMOUS MOTOR SPEEDWAY
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S COOKING UP
ONE OF MY FAVORITE FOODS
IN MASS QUANTITY.
I MEAN, THEY'RE MAKING
OVER 3,000 OF THESE A WEEK,
THAT'S OVER
A 150,000 A YEAR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK IT IS?
EXACTLY WHAT YOU EXPECT
TO FIND IN INDIANAPOLIS,
TAMALES
AT THE TAMALE PLACE.
(woman) TWO BEEF RED.
VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT'S AWESOME.
(woman) CHIPOTLE CHICKEN TAMALE.
IT'S A NICE SURPRISE
IN INDIANAPOLIS.
(woman) SWEET CORN AND CHEESE.
DID YOU KNOW
WHAT A TAMALE WAS?
NEVER TASTED ONE IN MY LIFE.
AS SOON AS THEY COME ONCE,
THEY'RE HOOKED.
TWO BEEF RED.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS THE BEST MEXICAN FOOD
I'VE EVER HAD.
ALL 'CAUSE ANGELA GREEN...
ORDER UP.
MET VLADIMIR RONCES IN MEXICO.
SLOWLY, WE GOT TO KNOW
EACH OTHER.
AND WHEN THEY DID,
THEY GOT MARRIED,
OPENED THIS JOINT
IN HER HOMETOWN...
OKAY, KIDS,
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE?
AND STARTED TURNING FOLKS
ON TO TAMALES.
THIS IS REAL DEAL.
SPICY CHIPOTLE CHICKEN--
REALLY GOOD.
PORK WITH RED SAUCE TAMALE
IS EXCELLENT.
CHICKEN VERDE TAMALE--
DELICIOUS.
AND THEN,
THERE'S THIS CLASSIC.
(woman) BEEF IN RED SAUCE
TAMALE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
FRESH COOKED BEEF
MADE IN THEIR CORN TAMALES.
THE MASA IS AWESOME.
MASA,
THAT'S DOUGH MADE FROM CORN...
THE KEY INGREDIENT
TO ANY GREAT TAMALE,
AND WE MAKE
FRESH MASA HERE.
THE WAY VLADIMIR LEARNED
TO DO IT FROM HIS FATHER.
RAW CORN, DRIED--THIS IS
TO GRIND UP TO MAKE THE MASA.
BUT FIRST,
WHAT DO WE GOT TO DO?
JUST GONNA PUT LIME IN.
THE LIME IN
THE BOILING WATER.
THEN THE CORN.
AND HOW LONG THIS GONNA BOIL,
FIVE MINUTES?
YEAH.
THEN IT'S COOLED.
HAVE TO WAIT 12 HOURS.
NOW IT'S READY TO BE RINSED.
GET THE SKIN OFF OF IT.
THERE WE GO, THE SKIN'S OFF.
AND NOW INTO THE GRINDER.
YEAH, THAT'S NICE.
HIT IT.
(motor whirs)
SO WHAT HE'S DOING IS HE'S
TRYING TO GET THE RIGHT GRIND.
LOOK AT THAT,
FRESH MASA, THAT IS KILLER.
NOW YOU TAKE THE MASA.
WE DIVIDE IT
IN 10-POUND PORTIONS.
FOR THE TAMALES
FOR THE BEEF IN RED.
GOT IT.
THIS IS GONNA MAKE THE
SHREDDED BEEF FOR THE TAMALE.
YEAH.
LOOK AT THE POT.
IT'S LIKE A MINI HOT TUB.
ONION, GARLIC.
GONNA DO THE MEAT.
YOU GOT IT.
YEAH!
GO FOR A 3-POINTER NEXT.
MORE ONIONS, SOME MORE GARLIC,
SALT, AND THEN SOME WATER.
THIS IS GONNA GO
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, BROTHER.
I LIKE THIS. THIS IS ALL
THE BASIS OF THE CHILI SAUCE?
ANCHO, GUAJILLOS...
PASILLA,
THEN THE PUYA.
MM-HMM.
NOW WE ADD WATER.
LET THEM STEEP.
SOAK OVERNIGHT.
REHYDRATE.
NICE AND SOFT, LOOK AT THIS.
FLESH COMES OFF.
OH, THAT'S IT, BABY.
THROW THEM IN THE BLENDER.
SALT.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
THEY PURéE REAL NICE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO WE'VE GOT THE PURéED CHILIES
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
NOW IT'S TIME TO MAKE
THE RED SAUCE.
GARLIC, ONION, BLACK PEPPER,
GROUND CLOVES...
OKAY.
SALT, TOMATOES, WATER.
AND THAT'S IT?
WE BLEND IT.
NOW THE TOMATO MIXTURE'S
DONE.
WE PUT SOME OF THIS PURE CHILIES
INTO THIS ONE RIGHT HERE.
ALL THAT TO COOK TO BEEF?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WOW,
LOT OF WORK, MAN.
SO WE GOT ALL THE BEEF
SHREDDED APART, COOL IT DOWN.
WHAT ARE WE UP TO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA FRY IT
A LITTLE BIT IN OIL.
ONIONS AND BURN IT
A LITTLE BIT.
TO FLAVOR THE OIL,
RIGHT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOT TO TAKE THE ONION OUT.
NOW WE DROP THE MEAT
IN THERE.
ALL THIS MEAT'S GONNA GO IN.
GETS A LITTLE BIT OF A FRY.
UH-HUH.
SOME OF THE RED SAUCE WE MADE,
8 GALLONS, SMELLS AWESOME.
SO HOW MUCH LONGER
IS THIS GONNA COOK?
15 MINUTES.
THEN WE TAKE IT TO THE MASA.
HE'S THE BOSS-A OF THE MASA.
UH-HUH.
SO THE MASA BALLED UP
AND READY TO GO.
WE GOT TO SEPARATE.
PUT THE OIL FIRST.
KIND OF CREAMS UP THE MASA.
SALT, BAKING POWDER.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES THEM
NICE AND LIGHT AND AIRY
AND NOT SUPER DENSE AND HARD.
NOW WE MIX IT.
HOW MANY TAMALES
WILL THIS MAKE?
70 TAMALES.
ABOUT 70?
MM-HMM.
WE ADD SOME RED SALSA.
SO WE MIX ALL THIS UP.
THEN WE START BUILDING TAMALES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOT IT.
SO WE GOT THE HUSKS THAT
HAVE BEEN SOAKED IN THE WATER,
SO THEY'RE NICE AND PLIABLE,
NICE BIG FAT ONES, TOO.
SOME OIL.
SO IT DOESN'T STICK.
PUT SOME MASA.
OKAY.
SOME SALSA.
OH, IT'S GONNA BE NICE
AND MOIST.
ADD SOME MEAT.
THAT'S GENEROUS,
BABY.
I HATE IT WHEN IT'S SO MUCH MASA
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT OF MEAT.
ROLL THE TAMALE, FOLD IT UP,
A LITTLE A BIT OF SALSA.
A LITTLE BIT MORE IN THERE.
YEAH, THERE WE GO.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA STAND
ALL THOSE UP IN THE STEAMER.
START IT FROM COLD,
STACK THEM UP,
35, 40 MINUTES
AND THEY'RE DONE.
THAT'S RIGHT,
THIS ONE'S READY.
ALL RIGHT.
THE SIZE OF THIS.
THAT'S HUGE, MAN.
MMM, THE MASA'S GOT
REALLY NICE FLAVOR TO IT, MMM.
AND THE MEAT INSIDE, NOTHING
LIKE SHREDDED MEXICAN BEEF.
MMM, GREAT JOB,
BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR TWO
BEEF REDS.
IT TASTES GREAT.
YOU CAN TASTE ALL
THE FLAVORS BLENDING.
IT'S REALLY KIND OF SWEET
AND BEEFY AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S BETTER THAN ANYTHING.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(Angela) SPICY
CHIPOTLE CHICKEN TORTA.
EVERYTHING I'VE HAD
IS DELICIOUS.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE ITEM?
STEAK TACO,
EVERYTHING ON IT.
IT'S THE CORN TORTILLA
THAT MAKES IT.
WHICH ARE HOMEMADE.
WITH THAT SAME FRESH MASA.
PUTS IT ON IT.
THEY MAKE THEIR CHIPS
WITH THE MASA.
IT'S JUST AWESOME.
MAKE THEIR DESSERT
WITH IT, TOO.
PINEAPPLE
AND RAISIN TAMALES.
THEIR SWEETS ARE AMAZING.
THE PUMPKIN TASTES BETTER
THAN PUMPKIN PIE.
(woman) APPLE PECAN TAMALE.
APPLE PECAN, THEY'RE GREAT.
YOU DON'T GET THOSE ANYWHERE.
'CAUSE THIS TAMALE,
ANGELA'S MOM CAME UP WITH.
WHERE DID SHE LIVE?
BAINBRIDGE, INDIANA.
IN BAINBRIDGE, INDIANA,
SHE MAKES TAMALES?
SHE DOES NOW.
SO HOW DO WE START IT OFF?
I GOT MY PLAIN MASA HERE.
REGULAR VEGETABLE OIL.
BAKING POWDER,
A LITTLE SALT.
READY?
I'M NOT DOING IT, YOU ARE.
GET IN THERE.
IT'S MASA WRESTLING HERE
LIVE AT THE TAMALE PLACE!
NEXT STEP, SUGAR.
THAT'S A LOT OF BROWN SUGAR.
SOME CINNAMON.
OKAY, APPLE PIE FILLING,
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST...
PECAN BITS.
AND NOW YOU'RE GONNA
MIX THIS ALL BY HAND?
I'M GONNA
GET IN THERE AGAIN.
YOU'RE GONNA GET UP
TO THE ELBOW.
I MIGHT, YEAH.
NOW I REFRIGERATE OVERNIGHT.
AND THEN WE MAKE
THE TAMALES WITH THAT.
EXACTLY.
IT'S TAMALE TIME.
OKAY.
LET'S GO, SMOOTH SIDE UP,
LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
THE MIXTURE, PUSH IT UP,
DOUBLE IT UP.
REALLY LOCK IT IN,
HUH?
MM-HMM.
IT'S VERY LABOR-INTENSIVE.
IT IS.
THIS IS GONNA GO INTO
THE STEAMING POT AS WELL.
IT WILL.
HOW LONG?
ABOUT 35 MINUTES.
THEN SERVE THEM.
APPLE WITH PECAN TAMALE.
GOT A LITTLE MEXICAN
APPLE PIE HERE.
DESSERT.
PECAN, CINNAMON,
BROWN SUGAR,
APPLE PIE FILLING...
MASA.
MMM, WOW.
YOU KNOW WHEN APPLE PIE
JUST CAME OUT OF THE OVEN
AND THE CRUST HASN'T REALLY
SET UP ON THE BOTTOM
AND IT'S GOOEY, CREAMY,
AND YOU GET ALL THE APPLE PIE
FLAVOR GOING ON?
THAT'S WHAT THAT'S LIKE,
GRANDMA'S APPLE PIE.
MY MOM'S.
SHE DID A GOOD JOB.
GOOD JOB, MOM.
HERE'S YOUR APPLE.
IT'S A FANTASTIC DESSERT.
IT'S SWEET
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
THE PECANS,
JUST PERFECT.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR FISH TACOS.
IT'S HOME-COOKED
AUTHENTIC MEXICAN FOOD.
TO FIND A PLACE LIKE THIS,
IT'S AWESOME.
SO YOU'RE LEADING THE TAMALE
REVOLUTION IN INDIANAPOLIS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU SEE IT EVERY DAY.
NEXT STOP,
WE'RE HEADING TO CHICAGO...
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
FOR A CULINARY WORKOUT.
YOU WANT ME TO HELP YOU?
(laughs)
NO.
YOU KNOW,
ONE OF THE THINGS I DIG
ABOUT HITTING
THE BIG CITY ON TRIPLE "D"
IS WE GET TO TRY
SOME ETHNIC RESTAURANTS
THAT YOU JUST DON'T FIND
IN OTHER PLACES.
SO HERE I AM,
ABOUT 10 MILES EAST
OF MIDWAY AIRPORT
IN CHICAGO
IN AN AREA KNOWN
AS MARQUETTE PARK.
NOW I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
SOME CARIBBEAN FLAVORS
FROM BELIZE.
THIS IS GARIFUNA FLAVA.
THE FOOD HERE IS AMAZING.
STEWED CHICKEN.
SORT OF A TASTE
TO THE CARIBBEAN.
SPLIT PEAS WITH PIG TAILS.
COCONUT FLAVORS.
HUDUT BARURU WITH FALUMOU.
THE FISH IS ALWAYS
JUST SO FRESH.
HERBS AND SPICES THAT WE USE
BACK HOME IN BELIZE.
THE CENTRAL AMERICAN COUNTRY
WHERE RHODEL CASTILLO...
THIS IS YOUR CHICKEN.
AND HIS WIFE YOLANDA...
FOR TABLE FOUR.
GREW UP.
THE GARIFUNA COMMUNITY,
WHICH IS IN
THE SOUTHERN PART OF BELIZE.
GARIFUNA.
GARIFUNA IS A NATION
OF PEOPLE.
WE GOT MOST OF OUR FOOD
FROM THE LAND AND FROM THE SEA.
PUTTING THOSE THINGS TOGETHER
WITH THE SPICES
DISTINGUISHES US
FROM OTHER CUISINES.
DOES IT EVER.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS.
HUDUT BARURU WITH TIKINI.
HUDUT BARURU--
THAT'S MASHED PLANTAINS--
AND THE TIKINI?
IT'S LIKE A SOUP WITH CABBAGE
IN IT AND FISH, DELICIOUS.
LET'S GET STARTED.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A ROUX FIRST.
OIL, FLOUR.
OKAY.
MAKE A ROUX
TO A DARK CARAMEL COLOR.
GET A LITTLE NUTTINESS
OUT OF THAT.
YES.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
YOU START WITH WATER.
ADD OUR VEGETABLES, ONION,
RED BELL PEPPER,
CARROTS, STIR IT UP.
WE'LL ADD
THE REST OF OUR SEASONING,
SOME OREGANO,
BLACK PEPPER, GARLIC.
I'M DOWN WITH ALL THIS.
LET THIS COOK
20 TO 30 MINUTES.
OKAY.
AND THEN
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
OUR FISH.
WHAT KIND OF FISH
ARE WE TALKING?
WE'RE USING KINGFISH TODAY.
GOYA SEASONING BOTH SIDES
AND LIGHTLY FRY IT.
WHOA, A LITTLE COLOR
AND LITTLE TEXTURE.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT IT IN
THE SOUP FOR 10 TO 15 MINUTES.
ADD OUR CABBAGE.
CABBAGE IS BIG
IN GARIFUNA CUISINE?
YES.
COOK FOR ANOTHER 10,
15 MINUTES.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'LL DO
OUR PLANTAINS.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
GREEN PLANTAIN, SWEET PLANTAIN,
PUT THE TWO OF THEM TOGETHER?
YES.
INTERESTING.
SLIT THEM DOWN.
OH,
THOSE ARE NICE.
CUT THEM IN HALF,
PUT THEM IN SOME WATER TO BOIL,
20 TO 25 MINUTES.
THEN WE'LL MASH.
AND THEN WE'LL MASH THEM.
WITH THIS UNIT RIGHT HERE?
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE USING
THE FOOD PROCESSOR,
WHICH DOES THE SAME THING.
NO!
(laughs)
NO, NO, NO.
THIS IS WHAT YOU USE,
BABY.
OF COURSE.
CAN I START?
I'M ONLY INTO IT
ABOUT TEN SECONDS AND I'M TIRED.
WANT ME TO HELP YOU?
NO.
YOU JUST ADD A LITTLE WATER
TO HELP SOFTEN IT.
SO WHO WAS THE GUY THAT SAID
DON'T USE THE FOOD PROCESSOR?
WHERE'S HE RIGHT NOW?
HOW DOES THAT LOOK?
LOOKS GOOD.
SO IT'S DONE.
OH!
THIS IS HOW IT LOOKS.
PLATE THE TIKINI.
THAT IS RICH.
HERE'S CABBAGE SOUP.
TAKE SOME OF THE HUDUT
AND YOU DIP IT IN YOUR SOUP
AND THAT'S HOW IT'S SEASONED.
MMM, JUST SAVORY.
REAL RICH FLAVOR
AND DELICIOUS.
THIS IS SOMETHING
YOU WANT TO COME TRY.
OH, I CAN'T PUT IT DOWN,
SERIOUSLY. MMM.
GREAT JOB. DELICIOUS.
THANK YOU, GUY.
HERE'S YOUR HUDUT BARURU
WITH TIKINI.
MADE IN THIS LOVELY SAUCE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WITH THAT LITTLE PEPPER,
VERY GOOD.
OXTAILS.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS SO GOOD.
FROM THE TRADITIONAL...
FALUMOU WITH KINGFISH.
TO A GARIFUNA TAKE
ON OTHER CULTURES,
LIKE A MEXICAN TOSTADA...
HERE'S YOUR GARNACHES.
VERY TASTY.
OR A SOUTH AMERICAN EMPANADA.
ORDER OF PANADES.
THERE'S FISH IN THESE,
VERY TASTY.
NOT JUST ANY FISH.
OH! WHAT IS THAT?
THAT'S A BUFFALO FISH.
THAT'S A HONKER.
WE'RE MAKING PANADES.
WE HAVE TO BOIL
THE BUFFALO FISH.
ONIONS, GREEN BELL PEPPER,
CELERY, BAY LEAF.
SOME CARROTS
AND SOME GARLIC.
THE BUFFALO FISH.
OH, MY GOSH.
LET THIS COOK.
30 MINUTES ON ONE SIDE,
30 MINUTES ON THE OTHER SIDE.
LET IT COOL.
TO DEBONE IT,
REMOVE THE SKIN.
TAKE THE FLESH OFF.
SO WE'RE GONNA FINISH
COOK THE FISH.
OIL, ONION, GARLIC,
GREEN BELL PEPPERS,
SOME OREGANO, THYME,
A LITTLE SALT.
ONCE THE PEPPERS AND ONIONS
SWEAT DOWN A LITTLE BIT,
WE ADD THE FISH.
YES. PAPRIKA,
SOME GOYA SEASONING.
SAZóN? (clicks tongue)
BLACK PEPPER.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
LOOKS BEAUTIFUL,
SMELLS BEAUTIFUL. MMM!
THIS WILL BE THE FILLING
FOR THE PANADES.
YEAH.
WE'LL MAKE A SAUCE.
OKAY.
CABBAGE, ONIONS, SALT,
HABANERO PEPPER,
SOME WATER.
AND A LITTLE VINEGAR.
THAT'LL BE HOT.
WHAT WE'LL DO NEXT
IS MAKE THE PANADES.
SO NOW THE MASA.
LET'S SEASON.
WITH THE SAZóN
AND THE SALT.
NOW I'LL MIX IT TOGETHER. WE'LL
ROLL THEM OUT INTO SMALL BALLS.
PUT THEM BETWEEN
PLASTIC SHEETS.
SO IT DOESN'T STICK
TO THE METAL, THERE YOU GO.
TAKE SOME OF YOUR FISH.
FOLD IT OVER.
OH, GONNA DO IT
RIGHT THERE.
BOOM, BOOM, BOOM.
READY TO GO.
I LIKE THIS.
DOWN, SQUEEZE, UP, OVER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA FRY THESE?
FRY THEM.
AND THIS IS HOW THEY LOOK
WHEN IT'S BEEN FRIED.
MMM. VERY SMOOTH TEXTURE,
LITTLE SWEET, NICE AND TENDER.
A LITTLE BITE OF HEAVEN.
MMM.
AND NOW THIS IS THE SAUCE.
IT'S HOT.
THE VINEGAR, THE HEAT.
(exhales sharply)
THIS YOU GOT TO TRY FOR SURE.
MMM, MMM, MMM, MMM!
(man) HERE'S YOUR PANADES.
THEY'RE VERY TASTY.
IT'S SUPER LIGHT.
I LIKE THE LITTLE SAUCE.
THE HEAT COMES UP AND
IT'S PERFECT ON TOP OF THE FISH.
IT'S HARMONIOUS.
A REAL HOME-COOKED MEAL.
STEWED CHICKEN COMING UP.
IT'S LIKE HAVING SUNDAY DINNER
WITH YOUR FAMILY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU HAD
ON YOUR SUNDAY DINNER
WITH YOUR FAMILY BUT I NEVER HAD
ANY PIGTAILS SPLIT-PEA SOUP.
EVERY OTHER DAY
WE HAVE IT IN BELIZE
AND I'M HAVING IT HERE.
THESE ARE SALTED PIGTAILS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM,
THAT WAS GOOD.
WELCOME BACK
TO GARIFUNA FLAVA.
WE'RE HERE
IN THE SOUTH SIDE OF CHICAGO
HANGING OUT
WITH YOLANDA.
AND, MAN, WE HAVE HAD
SOME DYNAMITE FOOD.
LIKE MASHED PLANTAINS
WITH FISH STEW...
MMM.
AND THE BELIZEAN-STYLE
EMPANADAS.
THIS YOU GOT TO TRY
FOR SURE, MMM!
BUT GET A LOAD
OF THIS AUTHENTIC CLASSIC.
SPLIT PEAS WITH PIGTAILS.
EVERY OTHER DAY
WE HAVE IT IN BELIZE.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
CHECK OUT THE PIGTAILS.
THESE ARE SALTED PIGTAILS.
OH, GOOD, 'CAUSE I JUST DO NOT
ENJOY THE UNSALTED ONES.
WE'LL PUT THEM IN THE BOILING
WATER. BOIL THEM FOR TWO HOURS.
MAKE THEM SOFT.
OOH.
TO MAKE THEM SOFT, RIGHT.
AND YOU HAVE TO CHANGE
THE WATER TWO, THREE TIMES.
SERIOUSLY,
SO THIS IS LIKE SALTED COD?
TO KIND OF TAKE OUT
SOME OF THE SALT.
SO THE PIGTAILS ARE DONE.
YES.
NOW WHAT'S ON?
SO WE'RE GONNA BOIL
OUR SPLIT PEAS.
SEASON WITH HAM HOCKS.
OKAY,
IS THAT SMOKED?
THIS IS SMOKED.
OKAY.
ONIONS, RED BELL PEPPERS,
AND OUR GARLIC,
AND WE LET THIS BOIL
ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
BLACK PEPPER, SALT,
OREGANO, SOME THYME.
SOME THYME.
CHICKEN SEASONING,
MIX THAT IN. HOW MUCH LONGER?
SAY ANOTHER 30 MINUTES.
WHEN'S THE PIGTAIL
COMING BACK IN?
WHEN THIS IS ALL SOFTENED.
SO WE'LL CHOP THEM UP FIRST.
THEN WE'LL ADD THE PIGTAILS.
GIVE IT SOME FLAVOR.
WE'LL ADD IN BUTTER.
WITH LE PIGTAIL.
COCONUT MILK. LET IT COOK
FOR ANOTHER 15 MINUTES.
I CAN'T WAIT.
IT'S MY PLEASURE
TO SERVE YOU A LITTLE.
THANK YOU.
SPLIT PEA SOUP
WITH PIGTAILS.
GENEROUS.
HOW WE'D EAT THIS...
OH, PLEASE.
WE TAKE A LITTLE
OF THE SPLIT PEAS.
OKAY.
PUT IT OVER THE RICE,
SOME OF YOUR PIGTAIL.
AND SOME OF MY PIGTAIL.
MMM, THAT WAS GOOD.
(laughs)
PIGTAIL IS A LITTLE--
IT'S FATTY.
MM-HMM.
BUT NOT FATTY CHEWY. ALMOST
LIKE BUTTER. LOTS OF FLAVOR.
MMM. I'M DOWN WITH THAT.
THE SPLIT PEAS,
THEY'RE COOKED DOWN SO MUCH,
IT'S LIKE A SPLIT PEA SAUCE.
REALLY NICE AND CREAMY.
FLAVOR'S GREAT.
LOOK AT THAT NICE LITTLE PIECE
RIGHT THERE, THERE YOU GO.
MY VOTE--PIGTAIL.
HERE'S YOUR SPLIT PEAS
AND PIGTAIL.
IT'S JUST A WONDERFUL DISH.
I LOVE HOW TENDER
THE PIGTAIL IS.
AND IT HAS
REALLY GREAT FLAVOR.
STEWED CHICKEN COMING UP.
IT REMINDS ME OF BACK HOME.
SPLIT PEAS AND PIGTAIL.
IT'S JUST GREAT FOOD,
AND IT'S A GREAT RESTAURANT.
(Yolanda) ORDER OF PANADES.
LOVE IT, LOVE IT.
GREAT JOB, YOLANDA.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S IT FOR
THIS EDITION OF TRIPLE "D."
YOU WANT TO GET THESE RECIPES,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
DON'T WORRY, WE GOT PLENTY
MORE JOINTS OUT THERE TO FIND.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DON'T TOUCH MY PIGTAIL.
WHICH DO YOU WANT TO TRY?
REALLY?
FROM THIS TO THIS.
(laughter)