HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(vocalizing)
WE'RE ROCKIN'
FROM THE OLD...
LIKE WORLD WAR II HERE.
TO THE NEW.
IT DOES GO PANINI?
YEAH, IT DOES.
YEP.
OH.
IN HAMTOWN, DETROIT...
THOUGHT I WAS GONNA HAVE
SOME OLD GUY BACK HERE.
ALL MEAN, CURMUDGEON-Y GUY...
(growling)
WE CAN GET ONE
IF YOU WANT.
YOU WANT
TO BRING ONE IN?
YEAH.
THE POLISH RESTAURANT...
FRIED KIELBASA'S READY.
SERVIN' UP OLD-WORLD TASTES
FROM THE CELLAR
SINCE THE '70s.
THAT'S ONE OF THE BEST
POLISH DISHES I'VE EVER HAD.
I CAN'T--
I CAN'T FIGHT IT.
IN VIRGINIA BEACH,
A ROADSIDE RESTAURANT...
YEAH, DON'T HAVE YOUR
OWN PRODUCE MARKET.
THAT'S NOT FAIR IN THE WORLD
OF RESTAURANT-ING.
WITH SCRATCH-MADE MEALS
THAT CAN'T GET ANY FRESHER.
I FORGOT
THE MOST IMPORTANT TOOL.
WE'RE GOGGLIN' UP.
AND IN VANCOUVER, B.C...
THIS TEMPLE WAS PARTIALLY
CREATED BY PULLED PORK.
(laughs)
DON'T LAUGH
AT THE TEMPLE.
THE RETRO JOINT DROPPIN'
FINE DININ'...
(man) COWBOY
WITH SCRAMBLED EGGS.
FOR FINE GRUB.
BURGER, FRIES.
NOW YOU'RE
IN THE KNOW.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN A TINY
2.5-SQUARE-MILE AREA OF DETROIT
KNOWN AS HAMTRAMCK
OR "HAMTOWN,"
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT.
NOW BACK IN THE 1930s AND '40s,
THIS HAD ONE OF
THE HIGHEST POLISH POPULATIONS
IN THE COUNTRY.
NOW THE NEIGHBORHOODS
HAVE CHANGED,
BUT SOME OF THE CULTURAL
CLASSICS STILL REMAIN.
WE'RE HERE TO CHECK OUT
POLISH VILLAGE CAFé.
FRIED KIELBASA'S READY.
THIS PLACE IS TRADITIONAL.
PICK UP
HUNGARIAN PANCAKE, PLEASE.
I'M HAVING
THE STUFFED CABBAGE.
I'M A STUFFED CABBAGE
JUNKIE.
STUFFED CABBAGE.
IF YOU CAN'T GET
TO POLAND,
COME HERE.
THIS IS POLAND.
IT'S BEEN AS CLOSE AS YOU
CAN GET TO THE OLD COUNTRY
SINCE CAROLYN WIETRZYKOWSKI'S
DAD TED OPENED IT IN '76.
HE'S POLISH,
100% POLISH.
OH, OKAY.
SO IT WAS A NO-BRAINER
WHEN SHE TOOK OVER THE JOINT...
MAKING PANCAKES.
AFTER LEARNING
ALL THE POLISH CLASSICS.
BEET SOUP READY.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS AUTHENTIC.
AND HOMEMADE, RIGHT DOWN
TO THIS POLISH FAVORITE...
(Carolyn)
HUNGARIAN PANCAKES.
A HOMEMADE HUNGARIAN PANCAKE
TOPPED WITH THEIR TAKE
ON GOULASH.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE A STEW ON TOP.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
MEAT IS THE BEGINNING
OF HUNGARIAN PANCAKE?
WITH GOULASH.
WELL, LET'S GET IT GOIN'.
WHAT ARE WE STARTING WITH?
THIS IS THE PORK BUTT.
AND THEN WE CUT IT UP,
BASICALLY MAKE STRIPS OUT OF IT,
AND GET RID OF THE FAT.
ZORRO CALLED.
YEAH.
HE WANTS
HIS KNIFE BACK?
NO, ZORRO JUST CALLED.
I DIDN'T...
OH.
NOW WE'VE GOT THE, UH, MEAT
ALL CUBED UP.
MM-HMM.
AND WHAT'S UP?
SEASON TIME?
YEP. FIRST, WE PUT
SOME SALT.
THOUGHT I WAS GONNA HAVE
SOME OLD GUY BACK HERE--
ALL MEAN, CURMUDGEON-Y GUY...
(growling)
WE CAN GET ONE
IF YOU WANT.
YOU WANT
TO BRING ONE IN?
YEAH. NEXT IS PEPPER.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA NEXT.
AND BAY LEAVES.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER, TOO?
YEP, JUST ENOUGH
TO COVER THE MEAT.
AND I PUT THE LID ON.
THIS IS THE LID?
MM-HMM.
DOESN'T FIT.
IT DOES.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS,
POP IT IN THE OVEN.
HOUR AND A HALF, FANTASTIC.
PULL IT!
LIKE WORLD WAR II HERE.
YOU READY?
I'M READY--WHAT,
SHOULD I DO A DRUMROLL?
OR WHAT DO YOU--
WHAT ARE WE GOING AFTER?
IT MIGHT HELP.
OKAY?
OKAY.
NICE. NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
THESE ARE THE PEPPERS.
AND THEN THERE'S
CELERY ROOT...
I LOVE CELERY ROOT.
AND HUNGARIAN PEPPERS,
CARROTS, AND ONIONS,
JALAPEÑO PEPPERS.
JALAPEÑO PEPPERS
IN POLISH FOOD?
YES.
YOU HAVE JALAPEÑOS
IN POLAND?
UH, OF COURSE.
AND MUSHROOMS.
(whistles) LOOK AT THAT MEAT
JUST FALL APART. TENDER.
IT TASTES GREAT
BY ITSELF.
IS ALL GOULASH MADE WITH PORK?
I MAKE MINE WITH BEEF.
SEEMS LIKE MOST PEOPLE
MAKE IT WITH BEEF.
DO YOU GUYS
MAKE IT WITH PORK
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE...
UNUSUAL, YEAH.
AND THEN THIS IS GONNA
GO BACK INTO THE OVEN
FOR ANOTHER
ABOUT HALF-HOUR.
WE'LL BRING IT OUT?
MM-HMM.
AND THEN WHAT'S
GONNA HAPPEN?
THEN YOU DRAIN IT,
AND YOU SAVE THAT SAUCE
TO MAKE THE GRAVY.
AND WHAT'S
THE GRAVY CALLED?
GRAVY SAUCE.
GRAVY SAUCE. OOH.
TIME TO MAKE THE PANCAKE.
OR ARM-WRESTLE.
UH, ARM-WRESTLE.
LET'S MAKE PANCAKES.
THIS IS
THE GROUND-UP POTATOES.
OKAY, NOW WHAT?
WE ADD THE ONIONS...
OKAY.
AND THEN PEPPER.
THERE WE GO.
NEXT, SALT. AND THEN THIS IS
THE STARCH FROM THE POTATOES.
REALLY?
YEAH. AND THEN WE
ADD THE EGGS.
WORK AS A LITTLE BINDER.
AND THEN WE MIX THAT IN.
THE NEXT STEP
IS TO ADD THE FLOUR.
OKAY.
AND THEN YOU MIX IT IN. I THINK
WE'RE LOOKIN' PRETTY GOOD.
IT'S GOOD.
YEP.
AND YOU FRY YOUR HAND,
OR ARE WE GONNA JUST--
NO, WE USE A SPOON.
THE NEXT STEP
IS TO FRY THE PANCAKE.
SO IT SITS THERE,
AND IT COOKS UP,
AND THEN YOU FLIP IT.
OOH.
YEP.
NICELY DONE.
JUDGES GIVE HER A 9.
SO WE CAN TURN IT UP NOW.
TALKING TO YOURSELF NOW?
MM-HMM.
AWESOME.
WELL, I'M ACTUALLY TALKING
TO THE PANCAKE.
TALKING TO THE PANCAKE?
(mouths words)
IT NEEDS ENCOURAGEMENT.
AND IT'S DONE.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE
A SAVORY FUNNEL CAKE.
SURE.
MMM.
IT'S LIKE
FRIED MASHED POTATOES.
MMM. OKAY, NOW WHAT?
NOW WE PUT ON
THE GOULASH.
SERVE UP THE LADLE
OF FUN.
AND THERE YOU ARE.
WOW. BOY, IS THERE
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
THIS HAS GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF BITE TO IT IN THE GRAVY.
ALL THOSE VEGGIES.
THE PORK IS MEGA TENDER.
YOU GET GREAT CRUNCH
STILL GOING FROM THE PANCAKE.
MMM.
THAT'S ONE OF THE BEST
POLISH DISHES I'VE EVER HAD.
AH. PERFECT.
TAKE IT AWAY FROM ME,
'CAUSE I'M GONNA...
(chuckles)
I CAN'T--
I CAN'T FIGHT IT.
ROCK STAR JOB.
YOU'RE MONEY.
THANK YOU.
THE HUNGARIAN PANCAKE
IS WHAT I GET MOST OF THE TIME
WHEN I'M IN HERE.
THE GOULASH IS EXCELLENT.
IN THE WORLD OF GOULASH THAT
YOU'VE HAD IN YOUR LIFETIME,
HOW DOES THAT RATE?
THE BEST.
POTATO AND CHEESE PIEROGI.
EVERYTHING
HAS ALWAYS GOT
A LITTLE TOUCH
OF HOMEMADE TO IT.
'CAUSE IT'S NOT JUST
MAIN COURSES
THEY'RE DOING IN-HOUSE.
(Carolyn)
CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP READY.
POLISH PEOPLE REALLY LIKE
THEIR SOUP.
DILL PICKLE SOUP READY.
THE DILL PICKLE SOUP'S
MY ABSOLUTE FAVORITE.
OKAY, NEXT UP?
DILL PICKLE SOUP.
OH. GREAT.
YOU READY?
I MEAN, I AM--
I-I LIKE DILL PICKLES,
NOT--I CAN'T SAY
I FREAK OUT ABOUT 'EM.
FIRST, WE ADD THE CARROT
AND THEN THE CUBED POTATOES,
SOME MARGARINE,
AND WATER.
WHERE'S THE, UH,
DILL PICKLE PART?
IT'LL COME LATER.
OKAY.
IF YOU PUT THE PICKLES IN EARLY,
IT TURNS THE POTATOES HARD
FROM THE SALT.
REALLY?
MM-HMM. SO THAT'S WHY
THEY HAVE TO WAIT.
WHAT WILL BE
THE NEXT INGREDIENTS?
UM, YOU ADD SOUR CREAM,
FLOUR, SALT MIXTURE,
WATER...
OKAY.
AND THAT THICKENS THE SOUP.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA
WHISK THAT IN THERE
SO IT TIGHTENS IT UP?
YEAH.
OKAY, WHEN WILL
THE PICKLES GO IN?
THAT'S--TA-DA, PICKLES.
AND THEN,
TA-DA, PICKLES?
YES.
SO WE ADD OUR PICKLES.
(whistles)
POLISH GATORADE.
YES.
AND THEN
THE PICKLE JUICE.
NOW HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS COOK?
YOU BRING IT TO A BOIL.
THE SOUP IS DONE.
DOES IT TASTE
SUPER PICKLE-Y?
WELL, YOU'LL FIND OUT
IN A SECOND.
MMM.
IT'S NOT AS HEAVY
AS I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA BE.
MM-HMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF TANG...
BUT NICE AND LIGHT.
IT'S GOT
A LOT OF BIG FLAVOR,
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT THE TEXTURE
OF THE POTATO THAT BACKS IT UP.
MMM. I'D DRINK THAT.
EXCELLENT.
ALL RIGHT,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CUTE AS A BUTTON.
(woman) THIS IS
OUR DILL PICKLE SOUP.
YOU DEFINITELY KNOW
IT'S DILL PICKLE SOUP.
IT'S GOT THAT
TANGY FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
ZINGY, BUT...
ZINGY?
ZINGY. IT'S GOT,
LIKE, A ZING TO IT.
(Carolyn)
SCHNITZEL'S READY.
WE'VE BEEN COMING HERE
FOREVER.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
WE EAT POLISH FOOD
WHEN WE'RE IN THE U.S.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. WHEW!
NEXT UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO VIRGINIA BEACH...
(man) DUCK BARBECUE,
SWEET POTATO BISCUIT UP.
WHERE A ROADSIDE STAND
MAKES THE PERFECT NEIGHBOR...
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
FOR THE FRESHEST JOINT
IN TOWN.
THERE'S NOTHING
I DO NOT LOVE ABOUT THIS.
♪♪
WE'RE HERE ON SHORE DRIVE
IN VIRGINIA BEACH,
RIGHT AT THE FOOT
OF THE CHESAPEAKE BAY
BRIDGE-TUNNEL,
WHERE A DUDE THAT WAS RUNNIN'
A PART-TIME PRODUCE STAND
DECIDED TO GO BIG
AND OPEN UP A SMALL,
11-TABLE RESTAURANT
SERVIN' SCRATCH-MADE FOOD
AND RUNNIN'
THE PRODUCE STAND OUT BACK.
THIS IS THE LEAPING LIZARD CAFé.
SEASON'S BEST
READY TO GO.
IT'S ALWAYS
GONNA BE FRESH
WHEN YOU COME
TO THE LEAPING LIZARD.
READY TO ROLL WITH
THE FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
EVERYTHING THAT HE USES
IS ORGANIC,
FRESH OUT OF THE GARDEN,
OR FRESH FROM ONE
OF THE LOCAL FARMERS.
SWEET POTATO BISCUIT SAMMIE
WITH DUCK BARBECUE UP.
CHICKEN SALAD.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
I JUST LOVE THE ECLECTIC,
FUN CAFé ENVIRONMENT.
BILLY DOES A GREAT JOB.
THAT'D BE BILL PRINCE,
WHO GOT THE INSPIRATION TO GO
FROM STAND TO FULL SERVICE
BACK IN '06.
SO YOU HAVE
A PRODUCE STAND...
UH-HUH.
A PART-TIME
PRODUCE STAND.
RIGHT.
WHEN DID YOU GET THE WILD IDEA
TO DO A RESTAURANT?
ABOUT EIGHT YEARS LATER.
QUICK THINKER.
EIGHT YEARS.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
THE MENU?
FRESHNESS,
THE WAY WE PREPARE IT.
MOST OF IT'S LOCAL SOURCING.
DUCK BARBECUE,
SWEET POTATO BISCUIT UP.
THE DUCK BARBECUE AND
SWEET POTATO--IT'S WONDERFUL.
SWEET POTATO BISCUITS? WHAT ARE
WE DOING WITH THESE BISCUITS?
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME DUCK
BARBECUE WITH OUR APPLE SLAW.
YOU GROW THESE?
WE GET 'EM RIGHT OUT
OF OUR PRODUCE MARKET.
YEAH, DON'T HAVE
YOUR OWN PRODUCE MARKET.
THAT'S NOT FAIR IN THE WORLD
OF RESTAURANT-ING.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA
SCORE 'EM.
IN THE OVEN, WHAT TEMP?
400 FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
FLOUR, BROWN SUGAR,
BAKING POWDER, SALT...
CINNAMON-AMON-AMON...
AMON-AMON-AMON.
AND NUTMEG, SOME PEPPER,
COLD BUTTER,
AND THEN WE'RE READY
FOR THE POTATOES.
PUT IT IN THE FLOUR.
YOU DON'T WANT 'EM DENSE
AND HARD. DON'T OVERWORK 'EM.
SO WE'LL JUST HAMMER THESE OUT.
NOW THIS SHOULD MAKE WHAT?
A DOZEN AND A HALF.
HIGH FIVE.
JUST KIDDING.
THE OVEN?
YES, SIR.
400?
ABOUT 14 MINUTES.
DUCK TIME?
DUCK TIME.
ORGANIC DUCK.
SCORE IT SO IT CAN RENDER
A LITTLE BIT QUICKER.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
WE WANT TO LET THIS
COOK DOWN ENOUGH
THAT WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO SHRED IT.
RIGHT.
WHAT TEMP?
350 FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
(Guy) SEE, IT'S HAVING
SAUSAGE FINGERS ALSO
THAT REALLY HELP WITH THIS.
THESE THINGS
ARE MADE FOR IT.
CLAWING AND TEARING
AT MEAT.
NOW WE'LL GO AHEAD AND DO
THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
START WITH OIL, ONION,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
SOME BROWN SUGAR.
ADD SOME KETCHUP,
A LITTLE O.J., TERIYAKI.
A LITTLE WORCESTER-
SH-SH-SHIRE...
YOU SAY IT MUCH BETTER
THAN ME.
A LITTLE DIJON MUSTARD,
SOME RED PEPPER
FOR A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
DON'T WANT
TO OVERSAUCE IT.
ACCENTUATE, NOT COVER.
EXACTLY. ON THE PLATE
IT GOES.
WE PUT THE APPLE SLAW,
WHICH IS REALLY GOOD STUFF.
OH, I LOVE APPLE SLAW.
LIKE THAT,
AND THERE YOU GO.
KINDA LIKE WHEN YOU EAT
A SWEET POTATO FRY.
THE NICE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE,
AND THEN IT'S NICE AND CREAMY
ON THE INSIDE.
GET A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT CINNAMON COMING THROUGH,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT NUTMEG
IN THERE.
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN,
THAT APPLE SLAW COMES IN
AND JUST KINDA CLEANS IT UP.
HOW MUCH IS THIS?
UH, IT'S $9.95.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I'M A FAN. NICE JOB.
I APPRECIATE IT.
(woman)
DUCK BARBECUE.
IT'S VERY MOIST,
VERY FLAVORFUL.
FLOUNDER UP.
IT'S THE FRESHEST FISH
YOU'LL EVER GET.
LOVE THE FRESH SEAFOOD
THAT THEY HAVE.
ROCKFISH OVER PARSNIP
AND SWISS CHARD.
THE ROCKFISH
AND THE PARSNIP PURéE,
WHICH YOU'VE ALMOST
COMPLETELY DESTROYED.
DELICIOUS.
(vocalizing)
OH, I'M SORRY.
WE'RE ON.
ROASTED PARSNIPS--NOT GONNA DO
ANYTHING FANCY WITH IT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA CHOP IT UP
A LITTLE BIT,
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER, WRAP IT,
ROAST IT FOR ABOUT
HALF AN HOUR.
ALL RIGHT, NICE AND GOLDEN.
AND THEN WE PUT IT
IN THE CUISINART.
THE "QUIZ-INART"?
ADD THE CREAM,
OUR SECRET INGREDIENT OLD BAY,
AND HONEY,
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
NEXT UP, WE'RE GONNA DO
SWISS CHARD. IT'S A ROUGH CHOP.
JUST LOOK AT THOSE COLORS.
A BLEND
OF DIFFERENT CHARDS.
AND THE LEEK NEXT.
NICE, LITTLE,
THIN CHOP.
PUT THE WHOLE MESS
IN THE WATER.
AND IF YOU JUST KINDA
AGITATE 'EM A LITTLE BIT...
EXACTLY.
THE SAND WILL FALL
TO THE BOTTOM.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTé IT--
A LITTLE OIL, A LITTLE GARLIC,
LEEKS, A LITTLE KOSHER SALT
AND PEPPER, LEMON WATER,
THE SWISS CHARD,
A LITTLE TERIYAKI.
ADD A LITTLE SESAME OIL.
SO WE'RE TAKING
AN ASIAN SPIN ON THIS.
IT'S KIND OF EVOLVED
TO THAT.
THAT WILTS A LITTLE BIT MORE,
AND WE'RE GOOD?
AND THEN WE'RE GOOD.
GREAT.
HOW ABOUT THAT?
HO!
JUST CAUGHT THIS MORNING.
CHESAPEAKE BAY
STRIPED BASS.
WELL, ROCKFISH
IS HOW I KNOW IT.
OH, YOU'RE JUST GONNA FILLET IT
RIGHT HERE AND NOW.
I FORGOT THE MOST
IMPORTANT TOOL.
GOGGLIN' UP.
HERE YOU GO.
"SUH-MOOTH!"
LOOK AT THAT NICE,
BIG, FAT FILLET.
AND THEN THE CHOICE SPOT
RIGHT THERE IN THE MIDDLE.
A LITTLE OIL,
A LITTLE OLD BAY.
GIVE IT A SEAR.
HIT BOTH SIDES
AND THEN INTO THE OVEN?
RIGHT INTO THE OVEN,
ABOUT EIGHT MINUTES.
ROCKFISH IS DONE.
(whistles)
GET OUR PARSNIP PURéE--
JUST A LITTLE BED.
NICE SWISS CHARD TOPPING.
NICE DINNER. YOU GET
THE CREAMY BUTTERINESS
OF THE PARSNIPS,
THE CHARD MIXTURE.
WITH THAT SESAME OIL,
AND THE LIGHT SEASONING
ON THE FISH--
GREAT COMBO, MAN.
ROCK STAR JOB.
DUDE, IT CAN'T GET
ANY BETTER.
BUT I HEAR IT'S GONNA
GET BETTER.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE HANGING
OUT HERE AT LEAPING LIZARD
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
WITH WHO?
CHEF ANNE.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE BIT.
♪♪
WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE AT LEAPING LIZARD
IN VIRGINIA BEACH,
AND THIS IS CHEF ANNE--
BIG SMILE.
HI.
ANNE AND OWNER BILL PRINCE
ARE SERVIN' UP A RIGHTEOUS
SCRATCH-MADE MENU,
WHICH MAKES A LOT OF SENSE
WHEN YOU'VE GOT A PRODUCE STAND
NEXT DOOR.
YOUR BEEF TENDERLOIN
AND YOUR ROCKFISH.
(woman) I CAN REMEMBER
WHEN THEY FIRST OPENED.
THEY SAID,
"WE DON'T OWN A FREEZER.
"YOU'LL NEVER HAVE
ANYTHING FROZEN.
"YOU'LL NEVER
HAVE ANYTHING CANNED.
IT'S ALWAYS FRESH."
(Anne) NEED A RUNNER
FOR ROCKFISH.
(man) I SWEAR, I THINK
IT JUST CAME OUT OF THE WATER.
BILLY DOES A GREAT JOB WORKING
WITH LOCAL FARMERS.
IT WAS STILL KICKIN'.
IT WAS STILL FLIPPIN'
RIGHT THERE ON THE PLATE.
YEAH.
I'VE GOT
A CHICKEN SALAD SANDWICH UP.
(woman) IT'S DELICIOUS,
AND IT'S SO MOIST.
THE VEGETABLES ARE CRISP,
BREAD IS FRESH.
THEY TAKE THEIR TIME, AND THEY
WANT IT TO TASTE FABULOUS.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
THIS IS OUR PEACH CHUTNEY
FOR OUR CHICKEN SALAD,
'CAUSE REALLY, THE FLAVOR
OF THE CHICKEN SALAD,
REALLY SETS IT APART.
FRESH PEACHES--CRUCIAL
TO HAVE THIS IN OUR CHUTNEY--
BELL PEPPER, RAISINS.
SO THIS IS GONNA SPEND
SOME TIME SIMMERING HERE
TO BREAK DOWN THOSE ONIONS
AND THOSE PEPPERS.
EXACTLY.
SUGAR, CINNAMON,
GROUND CLOVES.
YOU'LL REALLY START
TO SMELL THAT.
I CAN SMELL IT
RIGHT NOW.
IT SMELLS LIKE CHRISTMAS.
MY CHRISTMAS SMELLS
LIKE BOURBON, BUT...
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR DILUTED
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
STIR THAT UP.
LET THAT SIMMER.
EXACTLY.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUR BONELESS
SKINLESS CHICKEN.
SEASON IT UP--
SALT AND PEPPER.
ROAST IT IN THE OVEN.
SO THESE ARE
OUR ROASTED CHICKEN.
IT'S NICE AND COOLED DOWN,
SO I CAN GO AHEAD AND PULL IT.
WE DO THE OLD
FINGER METHOD.
I'M JUST GONNA ADD
A LITTLE TEXTURE TO THIS,
SO IT KIND OF BINDS TOGETHER.
THAT'S NICE.
I LIKE THAT STYLE.
NEXT UP IS OUR MAYONNAISE
AND YOGURT MIXTURE,
AND WE HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF CURRY IN HERE.
MIX THE CURRY, YOGURT, AND MAYO
AHEAD OF TIME,
SO THE CURRY OPENS UP
A LITTLE BIT.
LET IT WORK TOGETHER.
NEXT IS THE CHUTNEY WE MADE,
REDUCED DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
BIG CHUNKS.
SOME CHOPPED GREEN ONIONS,
CHOPPED ALMONDS.
TOASTED CHOPPED ALMONDS.
YES, TOASTED.
UH, A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
GONNA GIVE THIS A GOOD MIX
WITHOUT TOSSING IT EVERYWHERE.
I LIKE THIS IDEA OF HAVING
THE CHICKEN DONE
TWO DIFFERENT WAYS--
OF HAVING IT GROUND UP
SO IT KINDA WORKS
ITS WAY IN EVERYWHERE,
AND THEN HAVING IT SHREDDED.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS ON?
WE'VE GOT
OUR HOMEMADE BREAD.
IS THAT THIS BIG MONSTER
RIGHT HERE?
THAT'S THE MONSTER.
OOH.
I'VE BEEN HERE
SINCE 2:00 IN THE MORNING
BAKING THAT FRESH
FOR YOU.
OHH. DID YOU
REALLY BAKE THAT?
YEAH.
NO KIDDING?
GOSH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S THE BOUNTY
OF THE COUNTY.
FRESH TOMATO, AS THE THEME GOES,
RIGHT FROM THE BARN.
SOME SPRING MIX HERE.
PILE THAT ON.
IT DOES GO PANINI?
YEAH, IT DOES. YEP.
OHH!
JUST A LITTLE TOAST
ON THAT BREAD.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE WE GO.
NOW IT'S EVEN MORE
RIDICULOUS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ANNE,
I'M NOT LOOKING FORWARD
TO TRYING TO STAY CLEAN
IN THIS ONE.
I WOULDN'T SUGGEST IT.
NO.
I WAS WAITIN'
FOR THAT LOOK, GUY.
(laughing) YOU HAD ME
IN SUSPENSE.
THERE'S NOTHING
I DO NOT LOVE ABOUT THIS.
AND I THINK HAVING IT CUT
WITH THE YOGURT
DOESN'T MAKE IT
SO HEAVY.
RIGHT.
PEACH CHUTNEY, GREEN ONION,
ALMONDS--ALL GOES SO WELL.
THE TWO TEXTURES
OF THE CHICKEN--
TASTES LIKE I'M GETTING CHICKEN
IN EVERY BITE.
PLEASE DON'T TELL ME
THIS IS UNDER 10 BUCKS.
IT'S NOT EVEN PAST $9.
IT'S A CLASSIC
$8.95 SANDWICH.
HAS INFLATION NOT HIT THIS CITY?
HAS IT NOT HIT THIS AREA?
THAT IS SUCH
A GOURMET CHICKEN SANDWICH.
THAT ONE ROCKS.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
YOUR CHICKEN SALAD.
(woman) THAT BLEND BETWEEN
THE CHUTNEY AND THE CHICKEN
IS JUST A WONDERFUL,
SWEET FLAVOR
WITH A VERY HEALTHY
BALANCE.
WILL THEY SELL ME
A BAG OF BEANS?
AM I GONNA BUY THE MAGIC BEANS
THAT JACK BOUGHT?
IS THIS STUFF
REALLY UNDER 10 BUCKS?
(woman) IT IS.
WHAT'S GAS IN THIS TOWN,
A NICKEL?
UH, NO.
THAT'S WHY
EVERYBODY COMES.
THERE'S JUST
SOMETHING WONDERFUL
ABOUT THAT NON-PROCESSED--
EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
YOU CAN TASTE ALL THE FLAVORS
IN THE FOOD.
IT'S SUCH A QUAINT,
UNIQUE RESTAURANT.
I MEAN, THERE ARE VERY FEW
PLACES THAT ARE LIKE THIS.
(Guy) TO HAVE
THE RESTAURANT HERE
AND THE PRODUCE STAND
IN THE BACK--
I MEAN, YOU'RE LOOKIN' FOR
SOMETHING TO COME AND DO
FOR AN HOUR OR TWO, THIS IS
THE PLACE TO COME AND HANG OUT.
I APPRECIATE YOU COMIN'.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
THANKS FOR HAVIN' ME.
THANKS, GUY.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO VANCOUVER, B.C...
GATOR NUGGETS COMIN' UP
IN THE WINDOW.
FOR PULLED PORK...
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT THIS TEMPLE
WAS CREATED
BY PULLED PORK?
(laughs)
CANADIAN STYLE.
MY FIRST INTERNATIONAL
TRIPLE "D" PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
♪♪
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"--
WHAT'S IT ALL ABOUT?
WELL, IT'S ABOUT GREAT FOOD,
CHARACTERS,
AND THEIR STORY.
AND THAT'S JUST WHAT WE HAVE
HERE TODAY.
WE'RE IN THE WEST SIDE
OF VANCOUVER, B.C.,
TO CHECK OUT A FUNKY
LITTLE JOINT
WHERE TWO CHEFS WHO HAPPEN
TO BE HUSBAND AND WIFE
HAVE OPENED UP A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S SERVIN' UP
WHAT THEY CALL "FINE GRUB."
WELCOME TO JETHRO'S.
ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL,
WE'VE GOT PANCAKES.
CATFISH PO-BOY.
(man) COWBOY BREAKFAST.
BASICALLY COMFORT FOOD
FOR FOODIES.
GOLD RUSH.
THESE PANCAKES ARE THE SIZE
OF YOUR HEAD.
(man) THEY HAVE
THE GREATEST FOOD HERE.
JUST A CRAZY, DIVERSE MENU.
COVERING EVERYTHING,
FROM CHOCOLATE CHIP
BANANA BREAD FRENCH TOAST
TO GATOR NUGGETS.
GATOR NUGGETS COMIN' UP
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S THE FIRST TIME I'VE TRIED
IT, AND IT'S MARVELOUS.
BUT DOES IT TASTE
LIKE CHICKEN?
I DON'T THINK SO.
OKAY.
IT'S ALL ABOUT COMFORT FOOD
FOR EMILY JANE STUART
AND HER HUSBAND D'ARCY ALLEN.
(D'Arcy) PULLED PORK.
THEY OPENED THE JOINT
IN 2010...
NICE ONE, BABE.
AND GAVE IT A NAME
NOT USUALLY HEARD
THIS FAR NORTH.
DO YOU KNOW ANYBODY
NAMED JETHRO?
NO.
IS JETHRO A TRADITIONAL
CANADIAN NAME?
NO.
IS THE JETHRO
YOU'RE REFERRING TO
"THE BEVERLY HILLBILLIES"?
COULD BE.
I'LL NEVER TELL.
WHO CAME UP
WITH "FINE GRUB"?
WELL, IT'S WHAT IT IS.
COWBOY CUISINE.
YOU GUYS HAVE COWBOYS
UP HERE IN CANADA?
WE HAVE ONE OR TWO.
WE KEEP 'EM OUT BACK.
YEAH, PROBABLY WAITIN'
ON THEIR TOP SELLER,
THE PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
ALL RIGHT,
PORK IN THE WINDOW.
I AM A PULLED PORK
AFICIONADO.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
THAT THIS TEMPLE...
(laughs)
DON'T LAUGH
AT THE TEMPLE PART.
THIS TEMPLE
WAS PARTIALLY CREATED
BY PULLED PORK.
MAKE SURE YOU UNDERSTAND.
I RESPECT THAT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE MARINADE
FOR THE PULLED PORK.
EQUAL PARTS BARBECUE SAUCE.
ANY PARTICULAR KIND?
BULL'S-EYE.
WHITE DISTILLED VINEGAR,
LIQUID SMOKE,
WORCESTERSHIRE...
WORCESTER-SH-SH-SHIRE.
SOY SAUCE, MUSTARD.
MMM.
SO BONE-IN BOSTON BUTT--
GO FOR 24 HOURS.
THEN IT'S DOWN
FOR A 12-HOUR ROAST.
SLAW TIME.
APPLE-FENNEL SLAW.
SHREDDED APPLES,
SHAVED CABBAGE.
CABBAGE.
WE HAVE TOASTED-OFF
PICKLING SPICE.
I ALWAYS TOAST OFF
MY PICKLING SPICE.
MM-HMM.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
BROWN SUGAR,
CABBAGE, FENNEL..
"FEN-ELL."
SHREDDED APPLE...
BETTER GET GOIN' BEFORE
THOSE APPLES TURN ON YOU.
PICKLING SPICE.
PEPPERS, SALT.
AND HOT SAUCE. THIS IS HOW
YOU PUT IT TOGETHER?
YEAH.
MIX IT ALL UP
WITH GOD'S TOOLS--
WITH YOUR HANDS.
RIGHT, RIGHT, YEAH.
WORD ON THE STREET IS YOU HAVE
A LITTLE BIT OF BACKGROUND
IN ROCK 'N' ROLL AND FOOD.
DID SOME TOURING WITH
SOME ROCK BANDS AND STUFF,
CATERING.
WHAT BANDS?
FLEETWOOD MAC,
LINKIN PARK.
BOTH ENDS
OF THE SPECTRUM.
OKAY, SO WE LET THIS GO.
MACERATE OVERNIGHT.
AND WE'LL THROW IT
ON TOP OF THE PORK.
YEAH.
I'LL BE AT THE GIFT SHOP.
SO YOU BREAK IT UP INTO THIS FAT
THAT YOU'VE GOT IN HERE,
THIS BATH-O-FAT?
YEP.
NEXT UP?
MAYONNAISE ON THE BUN,
BARBECUE SAUCE
ON THE TOP.
SLAW.
HOT AND JUICY.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S IT.
MY FIRST INTERNATIONAL
TRIPLE "D" PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
MMM. IT'S GOT A REAL BROAD
RANGE OF FLAVORS,
EVERYTHING FROM THAT PICKLING
SPICE, WHICH I'M GETTING STRONG,
TO THE FENNEL--MMM--
THE RED BELL PEPPER,
THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
AND THEN THE--
THE PORK ITSELF
HAS GOT A DEEPER
THAN ROASTED PORK FLAVOR.
IT IS FINE GRUB.
THANK YOU.
WELL DONE.
THAT'S "BURGER, FRIES."
BURGER, FRIES.
FRIES. NOW YOU'RE
IN THE KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, DARLIN', I'VE GOT
A PULLED PORK AND FRIES.
IT'S GOT A NICE TANG TO IT,
A LITTLE SWEET.
THE PORK IS
MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH.
(D'Arcy) COWBOY
WITH SCRAMBLED EGGS.
(Guy) HOW NICE IS IT
TO FIND A PLACE LIKE THIS
IN YOUR OWN NEIGHBORHOOD?
YOU CAN STUMBLE HOME
IN A FOOD COMA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
FINE GRUB--
WEST SIDE.
OKAY, I GOTTA ASK,
HOW MUCH DID THAT HURT?
NOT AT ALL.
(winces)
I'VE HAD A BABY.
THIS IS NOTHING.
IF THERE'S BABY NUMBER TWO,
AND IT'S A BOY,
WILL IT BE A JETHRO?
NO, IT'LL BE A GUY.
GUY. GUY.
I'LL BE A GUY.
YES!
GOOD NIGHT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
JUST... (laughs) NO, YOU'RE
MISSIN' IT. YOU'RE MISSIN' IT.
RIGHT--YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
YOU GOT IT.
I KNOW HOW
TO PAY ATTENTION.
(laughs)