HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LOOK AT THAT.
GRILLIN' AND SMOKIN'...
OH, MY GOSH. MMM.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
THE SPICY BURGER.
THE 60-YEAR-OLD DRIVE-IN...
Y'ALL READY
FOR THIS?
OH, YEAH.
SMOKIN' BRISKET...
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
AND BRINGIN' THAI FLAVOR...
SUPER HOT.
TO BURGERS.
MMM. HO! HOT.
IN DENVER...
WILD RICE AND CORN.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
FANTASTIC FOOD.
GRILLIN' UP...
LOOK AT THE GREAT COLOR
ON THAT.
NATIVE AMERICAN
TRADITIONS...
CHICKEN INDIAN TACO.
MMM. OFF THE HOOK.
AND THEN SOME.
BLUEBERRY
BARBECUE SAUCE.
MMM. ON POINT
WITH THAT ONE.
AND IN
ST. PETERSBURG, FLORIDA...
MEAT LOAF.
THE 59-YEAR-OLD
GENERAL STORE...
CONSISTENTLY GOOD
COMFORT FOOD.
WHERE A DINER CLASSIC...
(man) TEXAS HASH.
IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
IS SMOKED AND GRILLED.
IT'S A FATTY PATTY.
MMM. WHEN I COME BACK
TO ST. PETERSBURG,
I'M LOOKIN' FOR THAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO WE'RE ON THE NORTHEAST SIDE
OF SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
ON THE OLD AUSTIN HIGHWAY
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S BEEN SERVIN' UP
BURGERS AND BARBECUE
TO THE FINE FOLKS OF SAN ANTONIO
FOR OVER 60 YEARS.
THIS IS THE BUN 'N' BARREL.
(woman)
CAN I HAVE CHEESEBURGER?
OH, WONDERFUL.
ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
LOVE THE RIBS.
THAT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
(woman)
SLAB BRISKET SANDWICH.
TENDER. IT'S SMOKY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BURGERS AND BARBECUE.
THE COMBO THAT'S HAD FOLKS
PULLIN' IN...
(car horn honks)
SINCE THE '50s.
Y'ALL READY
FOR THIS?
OH, YEAH.
I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE SINCE
I WAS, LIKE, 4 YEARS OLD.
SO WHEN SYNGMAN STEVENS...
I NEED
A SLICED BEEF SANDWICH.
AND HIS WIFE
CHARASSRI SAENG-ON...
ANGUS BURGER READY.
BOUGHT THE JOINT...
WE TRY TO KEEP IT
OLD-SCHOOL,
WANT TO KEEP
THE LEGACY GOING.
AND THAT MEANS
BARBECUED CHICKEN...
CHICKEN BARBECUE
IS VERY GOOD.
BARBECUED RIBS...
ALMOST LIKE FALLING
OFF THE BONE.
AND THIS TEXAS
BARBECUE CLASSIC.
BRISKET SANDWICH.
BRISKET IS FABULOUS.
SOMEBODY THEY GOT
IN THAT SMOKEHOUSE
IS DOING
THE RIGHT THING.
THAT'D BE JOE FRIDAY.
YEP, THAT'S REALLY
WHAT THEY CALL HIM.
(Joe) THERE'S
A BRISKET.
AND HE'S BEEN WORKING
THE PIT HERE FOR 35 YEARS.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE
WE DOIN', MAN?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
BRINE THE BRISKETS.
YOU WANT ALL THE FAT
LEFT ON.
ALL THE FAT ON 'EM.
2 QUARTS SALT
AND THEN WATER.
AND THE BRISKET.
GREAT BRISKET.
NOW WE PUT THE ICE.
HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA BRINE?
24 HOURS.
NICE. NOW WE MAKE
THE DRY RUB?
WE START WITH
THE FINE PEPPER.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GET
ALL UPPITY ABOUT IT.
(groans)
COARSE PEPPER, SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
COMINO, PAPRIKA,
CHICKEN SEASONING,
WITH BROWN SUGAR.
THAT'S A FIRST.
NOW WE RUB OUR BRISKET.
I DO THIS
IN THE MORNING.
AND THEN YOU THROW 'EM
ON THE SMOKER
AT THE END
OF THE DAY?
OF THE DAY.
AND WHAT ARE WE
SMOKING 'EM WITH?
OAK.
AND LOOK AT THIS
BEAUTIFUL MESQUITE.
I LIKE IT.
(grunts)
(imitating Schwarzenegger)
I ONE-HAND THIS ONE.
JA, THAT'S RIGHT,
I GIVE IT TO HIM.
(normal voice) HOW LONG
WE GOIN' IN? HOW LONG--
14 HOURS.
YEP. 14 HOURS LATER...
NICE AND SMOKY.
OH, MY GOSH.
NICE BARK. GOOD SMOKE.
MMM. THAT'S
GOOD FLAVOR, MAN.
MMM. IT DOESN'T EVEN
NEED SAUCE.
THEN AGAIN...
IF YOU GET
THE SPICY BRISKET,
IT'S GOT THAT LITTLE BIT
OF KICK TO IT.
THANKS TO THE NEW
BARBECUE SAUCE...
THAT SAUCE
IS PERFECT.
FROM CHARASSRI'S
OWN RECIPE.
KINDA SWEET
THAI HOT SAUCE.
SPICY BARBECUE SAUCE.
ALL OF THIS
IS GOING IN?
YES.
GET READY.
PUT THE OIL.
THAT IS SO MUCH
GINGER AND GARLIC.
THAT'S RI-DONK-ULOUS.
AND NOW WHAT?
TWO CAN
OF TOMATO KETCHUP.
CLEAN IT OUT
AND GO GET WATER?
YES. WE'RE GONNA
ADD BROWN SUGAR.
WHEN DID I BECOME SOUS-CHEF?
WHAT IS THAT, TAR?
WET TAMARIND.
WET TAMARIND
AND PALM SUGAR. OH.
I'VE HAD THAT A LOT OF TIMES.
I USUALLY BRUSH WITH IT.
OKAY, BLACK PEPPER--
THE FINE AND THE COARSE.
AND THEN CUMIN.
YES, CHEF.
SRIRACHA.
HOW MUCH SRIRACHA?
WHOLE BOTTLE.
GARLIC POWDER--
WHOLE THING.
STEAK SAUCE?
STEAK SAUCE.
DID YOU JUST MAKE
THIS RECIPE UP, LIKE,
WITH WHAT YOU HAD LEFT
IN THE CUPBOARD?
(laughs)
WORCESTERSHIRE NOW?
WASABI.
THAT'S ENOUGH
TO KILL YOU.
HOT MUSTARD.
CHILI-GARLIC SAMBAL--
THAT MUCH?
THAT MUCH.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
FRIED CHILI PASTE?
YES.
THE ONLY THING
WE HAVE LEFT TO ADD.
(laughs)
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK?
AN HOUR SLOW COOKING.
(whistles)
THAT'S PRETTY TASTY.
SO THAT'S GONNA COME
ON THE BRISKET?
ON THE BRISKET.
AND THEN YOU MAKE
THE SANDWICH.
YES, SIR.
SLICE THE MEAT.
OKAY. I SHOULD
PROBABLY TRY THAT
JUST TO MAKE SURE
THAT'S OKAY. OH.
PUT ABOUT FOUR PIECES
ON THE BUN.
SPICY BARBECUE SAUCE.
DON'T BE SHY.
IN THE BUN.
AND NEXT, CUT IN HALF.
LOOK AT THE SIZE--
IT'S THAT THICK.
AND WITH
THE ONION RINGS.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
GOOD TEXAS BRISKET.
YOU GOTTA HAND IT TO JOE.
HE DOES A REAL NICE JOB
ON THE PIT. MMM.
THE SAUCE HAS GOT GREAT TANG
WITH A KICK.
THAT'S HOW I WANT IT.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
I'LL COME BACK FOR ONE
OF THOSE IN A HEARTBEAT.
THERE YOU GO--
A SLICED BRISKET.
THE BRISKET
IS WONDERFUL.
GREAT CHAR,
GOOD SMOKE FLAVOR.
THERE'S YOUR
SPICY BRISKET.
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF THAI
SAUCE--GREAT COMBINATION.
(Charassri)
CHICKEN BARBECUE READY.
EVERYTHING'S
GOOD HERE.
THE FOOD IS GREAT,
ALWAYS GOOD SERVICE.
Y'ALL ENJOY.
OKAY.
I USED TO COME TO THIS PLACE
WHEN I WAS 16 YEARS OLD.
AND THERE'S A GOOD CHANCE
LISA CROW...
HI, HOW Y'ALL DOIN'?
WAS WAITIN' ON HIM.
I STARTED HERE IN 1974.
I LOVE MY CUSTOMERS.
ALL RIGHTY.
THEY COME IN. THEY DON'T EVEN
HAVE TO TELL ME WHAT THEY WANT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU
IN A WHILE.
I JUST TELL HER
"THE USUAL."
AND IN 37 YEARS...
I'VE MADE A LOT
OF MILK SHAKES.
AND SERVED
A LOT OF BURGERS...
HERE'S YOUR ORDER.
FROM THE BARREL...
THEIR ORIGINAL BURGER HERE.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
TO THE LATEST FAVORITE.
SPICY THAI BURGER.
(woman)
THIS IS NEW FOR ME.
AND IT'S GOOD?
IT'S VERY GOOD.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
SHE PUTS IN THERE,
BUT IT'S GOT
A LITTLE ZING TO IT.
A LITTLE ZING?
THAI CHILIES
ARE SUPER HOT.
AND CHARASSRI'S
GROWIN' IT RIGHT OUT BACK.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A SPICY BURGER.
DOESN'T LOOK GOOD
FOR THE GUIDO.
HOT PEPPER, GARLIC.
CHOP REALLY FINE.
(exhales sharply) HO!
THIS IS GETTI''
MIXED INTO IT?
YES.
I'M OUT.
(laughs)
THIS IS GONNA BE HOT.
CHICKEN SEASONING.
AND THAT'S GONNA MATTER?
MIX IT UP. LET IT SIT
FOR, LIKE, 20 MINUTES,
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA MAKE A PATTY.
I'M SORRY.
IS FRED FLINTSTONE
COMING OVER?
(laughs)
THIS SHOULD BE
ABOUT 1/2 POUND.
1/2 POUND, YEAH.
I'D SAY SO.
HOW ARE WE LOOKIN'?
YOUR SPICY BURGER
LOOK GOOD.
WE ADD THE CHEESE.
SWISS?
WE WARM THE BUN.
THAT'S GONNA
BE SPICY, HUH?
MY NOSE IS ON FIRE.
WE USE A SPECIAL MAYO.
REALLY SUPER THICK
JAPANESE MAYO.
SPRING MIX,
RED ONION, TOMATO.
I LIKE IT.
LOOK GOOD?
THAT'S GOOD.
AND THEN WE PUT
AVOCADO.
BECAUSE WE LIVE IN TEXAS,
WE PUT AVOCADO.
'CAUSE WE LIVE IN TEXAS?
(laughs) OKAY,
THAT'S THE SPICY BURGER.
YOU NEED
TO TAKE A BITE.
MMM.
HO! HOT. WOW,
THAT'S REALLY WARM.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE HEAT TO IT,
NOT VINEGAR-TABASCO HEAT,
JUST ROUND CHILI HEAT,
BUT IT'S PRETTY ADDICTING.
MM-HMM. TASTY BURGER.
REALLY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
THE SPICY BURGER--
REAL HOT, BE CAREFUL.
YOU CAN HANDLE
THE HEAT?
YES, I CAN.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
CAN I HAVE FRENCH FRY
WITH THAT COMBO
SANDWICH?
THE FOOD
IS TO DIE FOR.
GREAT PEOPLE,
GREAT FOOD...
IS EVERYTHING
TASTIN' ALL RIGHT?
THAT'S WHY IT'S BEEN AROUND
FOR SO LONG.
WE KEEP COMIN' BACK.
CONGRATULATIONS, GUYS.
REALLY NICE PLACE.
ALL RIGHT,
THANK YOU.
VERY NICE
TO MEET YOU BOTH.
UP NEXT...
VERY UNIQUE
AND DIFFERENT.
WE'RE HEADIN' TO DENVER...
(man) GOT ONE RIB.
FOR RIBS WITH A TWIST.
BLUEBERRY SAUCE
IS TO DIE FOR.
HUGE FLAVOR.
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF MY FAVORITE
ASPECTS OF FOOD IS ITS HISTORY.
I MEAN, I WANT TO KNOW
THE WHO, WHERE, WHEN, WHAT,
AND WHY ABOUT IT.
NOW ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE'VE LEARNED A LOT
ABOUT ITALIAN FOOD,
MEXICAN FOOD,
COMFORT FOOD, I MEAN,
YOU-NAME-IT FOOD.
BUT ONE OF THE FOODS
WE HAVEN'T LEARNED ABOUT
IS NATIVE AMERICAN FOOD.
AND THAT BRINGS US HERE
TO DENVER, COLORADO,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
CALLED TOCABE,
AN AMERICAN INDIAN EATERY.
(man) MAY I HAVE
A RIB, PLEASE?
FANTASTIC.
GREEN CHILI STEW'S READY.
VERY UNIQUE
AND DIFFERENT.
LET ME DO
A SHREDDED BISON TACO.
FANTASTIC FOOD,
VERY NICE PEOPLE.
AND THEN FOR SALSAS,
I'VE GOT
AN OSAGE HOMINY.
(man) CULTURAL HERITAGE
AT ITS FINEST.
THESE GUYS DEFINITELY KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
THAT'D BE OSAGE NATION
TRIBAL MEMBER BEN JACOBS...
BLACK, PINTO,
OR CHILI BEANS FOR YA?
AND HIS COLLEGE BUDDY
MATT CHANDRA...
ANCHO-CHIPOTLE?
WHO OPENED THIS NATIVE AMERICAN
JOINT TWO YEARS AGO...
NAVAJO BLUE CORN
WITH CRANBERRIES.
TO SHARE THE FOOD
BEN GREW UP LOVIN'.
A BIG PART OF WHO
INDIAN PEOPLE ARE
IS GETTING TOGETHER
AND FEASTING.
ON SWEET CORN SOUP...
GREAT WITH FRY BREAD.
WILD RICE...
REALLY GOOD.
AND THIS FAVORITE...
CHICKEN INDIAN TACO.
I GREW UP EATING
INDIAN TACOS.
IT'S SO GOOD.
AND FRY BREAD...
A STAPLE OF AMERICAN
INDIAN CULTURE.
IT IS GREAT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
WE'RE STARTING
WITH OUR FRY BREAD.
HONEY WATER.
WATER AND HONEY,
I TAKE IT?
YES, SIR. MILK.
FROM THE COW.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR?
BAKING POWDER.
WE'LL GIVE IT
A COUPLE MINUTES.
OKAY.
DOUGH'S MIXED.
WORK IT IN A LOAF THERE.
SPLIT IT UP.
GRAB IT UP.
SPIN IT AROUND. GET YOURSELF
A NICE DOUGH BALL THERE.
TURNING IT IN ON ITSELF.
WE GONNA LET THIS PROOF?
RIGHT ON THE TABLE HERE.
WHEN YOU ORDER IT, WE MAKE IT.
ROLL IT TO A NICE EVEN CIRCLE.
THAT'S PERFECT.
OKAY.
TOSS IT
BACK AND FORTH.
WHOA, GOSH,
THIS IS THIN.
HOLE IN THE MIDDLE LETS THE OIL
COME RIGHT UP THROUGH.
IT COOKS MORE EVENLY. TOSS
THAT BAD BOY RIGHT IN THERE.
I THINK I JUST TURNED IT
INTO A PITA.
LET IT GO
FOR ABOUT 30 SECONDS.
FLASH-FRIED--
IN, OUT.
DIG THAT.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT WE'RE GONNA MAKE NOW,
BUT IT INVOLVES HOMINY,
WHICH I LOVE.
YEP.
IT'S AN OLD OSAGE DISH.
IT'S OSAGE HOMINY SALSA.
HOMINA, HOMINA,
HOMINA.
WE THROW IT
RIGHT IN THERE.
RED ONIONS IN, CUMIN.
COMINO, OKAY.
FRESH GARLIC, SERRANO PEPPERS--
A LITTLE KICK IN THERE.
MILD CHILI POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER,
KOSHER SALT, CILANTRO, SUGAR
TO SWEETEN UP THAT HOMINY.
REALLY?
YEAH. LEMON JUICE.
GOTTA HAVE
THE ACID BALANCE.
VINEGAR, CANOLA OIL.
AND THEN THIS IS WHERE
IT GETS WEIRD.
DRIED CRANBERRIES.
THIS IS WHERE IT GETS DELICIOUS.
GIVE THAT A WHIRL.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT'S GOOD.
AND WE ARE INTO...
CHICKEN MARINADE
FOR OUR CHICKEN TACO.
SOME CLOVES IN,
GARLIC, CINNAMON.
REALLY?
CINNAMON POWDER.
CINNAMON
IN INDIAN FOOD.
YEP, YEP.
NOW THIS IS ACHIOTE PASTE.
IT ADDS GREAT COLOR.
TURN THAT BAD BOY ON. NEXT WE
ADD CANOLA OIL--HALF OF IT.
THROW OUR VINEGAR IN.
WHAT THIS DOES TO CHICKEN,
AND THE COLOR IT'LL PUT ON IT--
OH.
OH, YEAH. FINISH OFF OUR OIL.
THEN WE ADD OUR HONEY REAL SLOW.
THIS IS A CONCOCTION.
KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
MMM.
GET OUR MAYONNAISE IN IT,
OUR ACHIOTE BLEND,
WATER HERE, AND THEN WE'LL
JUST MIX THIS UP.
IT'LL COAT TO THAT CHICKEN
REALLY WELL.
CHICKEN THIGH, HUH?
YEP.
BIG FAN OF CHICKEN THIGH.
GOOD JUICINESS IN THERE,
A LOT OF GOOD FLAVORS.
THEN WE JUST GET IN.
SO THIS WILL MARINATE
FOR 24 HOURS?
YEP. CHICKEN
IS MARINATED.
DIG IT.
WE LIKE TO GRILL IT SO WE GET
A NICE SEAR ON THERE.
SALT AND PEPPER
JUST ON TOP.
FLIP IT,
MARK THE OTHER SIDE,
SHEET TRAY, FINISH IT
IN THE OVEN, 15 MINUTES.
YEP.
OH, LOOK AT THE GREAT
COLOR ON THAT.
NICE AND JUICY STILL.
THEN WE CHOP IT.
YOU READY?
CHOP IT UP.
LET'S GO.
GOTTA HAVE THE BREAD THERE.
START WITH SOME BLACK BEANS,
THE CHICKEN WE MADE EARLIER,
LETTUCE, CHEESE.
IS THIS "ANIMAL HOUSE"?
ARE WE GONNA GO
RIGHT DOWN THE BUFFET?
OH, YEAH. WHAT CAN I SAY?
WE WANT YOU TO BE FULL.
YOU GOTTA HAVE THE HOMINY,
SOME GREEN CHILIES, ONIONS.
ENOUGH ALREADY.
TOMATOES. MAKE IT LOOK REAL
PRETTY WITH THE SOUR CREAM.
WOW.
THE FRY BREAD
IS THE BOMB. MMM.
WITH THE CHICKEN
THAT'S BEEN MARINATED
AND THE COMPLETELY
OFF-THE-HOOK HOMINY SALSA,
YOU'RE GONNA MESS UP THE WAY
PEOPLE LOOK AT A TACO. MMM.
AWESOME,
AWESOME JOB.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU THE MAN.
CHICKEN INDIAN TACO.
JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
THE FLAVOR OF THE CHICKEN
IS DELICIOUS.
HOMINY SALSA
IS THE BOMB.
GREEN CHILI STEW.
NOT LIKE ANYTHING
I EVER HAD BEFORE.
DO THE MAJORITY OF PEOPLE KNOW
WHAT AMERICAN INDIAN FOOD IS?
WE HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
COME IN THAT ARE BRAND-NEW,
AND THEY WANT US
TO KIND OF WALK 'EM THROUGH
HOW OUR FOOD'S
REPRESENTED.
AND HOW IT'S CHANGING...
SHREDDED BISON,
RIGHT?
LIKE THIS
NATIVE CLASSIC...
BISON RIBS.
WITH A NEW TWIST.
BLUEBERRY
BARBECUE SAUCE.
I LOVE THE RIBS.
THOSE ARE MY FAVORITE.
AND THE BLUEBERRY SAUCE
IS TO DIE FOR.
MAN, YOU'RE JUST
ROLLING OUT THE SPICES.
GOT TO.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO NOW?
DRY RUB
FOR OUR BISON RIBS.
PAPRIKA, MUSTARD POWDER.
THAT'S VIBRANT.
GUAJILLO PEPPER.
REALLY NICE,
MEDIUM HEAT.
MILD CHILI POWDER,
CELERY SALT,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
SOME SAGE.
MMM.
BISON AND SAGE?
OH, YEAH.
BLACK PEPPER, SALT.
GET A NICE COLOR ON THERE.
OKAY.
THOSE ARE OUR RIBS.
FLIP 'EM OVER HERE.
WE GOT A MEMBRANE
ON THE BACK.
THERE YOU GO.
COMES OFF
NICE AND CLEAN.
WAY TO GET
AFTER THAT.
THERE WE GO.
DRY RUB ON THERE.
OIL. RUB IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
PUT SOME BROWN SUGAR
ON TOP.
SO YOU ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEETNESS TO IT.
YEP. WRAP IT UP WITH PLASTIC.
THROW 'EM IN THE REFRIGERATOR.
24 HOURS.
READY TO GO?
GONNA GRILL THESE UP.
SO YOU PUT
A LITTLE COLOR,
PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON 'EM.
UH-HUH.
LOOK AT THAT.
HOLD ON.
WE GET OUR PAN SCRAPINGS
FROM THE DRY RUB.
GOTTA HAVE BEER IN THERE.
THEN WE GRAB OUR RIBS.
LAY 'EM IN.
WE GONNA FOIL
THIS BAD BOY?
YES, WE ARE.
WE LOCK IT REAL TIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
TO THE OVEN?
TO THE OVEN.
WE DO ABOUT 350.
350.
AN HOUR AND 45 MINUTES.
WHILE THOSE RIBS COOK,
WE GOTTA MAKE THE BLUEBERRY
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE'LL THROW IN WATER
AND SUGAR.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
SOME CHIPOTLE PEPPERS.
THE ADOBO SAUCE.
BLUEBERRIES.
THAT'S SOME BLUEBERRIES.
FRESH MINCED GARLIC,
HONEY.
GET THAT ALL IN THERE.
BARBECUE SAUCE BASE.
A HINT OF THAT
SMOKINESS.
JUST A HINT. WE'LL ADD
SOME KOSHER SALT.
MIX IT ALL IN.
HOW LONG DO WE
LET THAT SIMMER?
ABOUT TWO HOURS.
LET THE BERRIES BREAK DOWN
A LITTLE BIT?
THICKEN UP,
AND THEN WE'LL MIX IT ALL UP,
STRAIN OUT THE LAST LITTLE BIT
OF THOSE BERRIES,
AND IT'S READY TO GO.
LOVE IT.
RIBS ARE DONE.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. FANTASTIC
THAT WAY.
CUT YOU A NICE
HEALTHY PORTION HERE.
THROW ONE ON THE GRILL. THERE'S
OUR BLUEBERRY BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE GOTTA HAVE
THE BREAD, RIGHT?
I GUESS.
GET YOU THAT BAD BOY.
SO WE GOT A NICE LITTLE SEAR
ON OUR SAUCE. TAKE 'EM OFF.
GET YOU SOME EXTRA SAUCE.
THERE IT IS.
THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE. MMM.
DELICIOUS. IT'S GOT
HUGE, HUGE FLAVOR.
NICE AND TENDER.
GIVE IT A LITTLE DUNK. MMM.
AND YOU COMPLEMENT IT REALLY
NICELY WITH THE BLUEBERRY.
ON POINT
WITH THAT ONE.
AWESOME.
(man) GOT ONE RIB.
THEY'RE FANTASTIC.
BIG AND MEATY,
AND THE SAUCE IS WONDERFUL.
JUST AWESOME.
WILD RICE AND CORN.
EXCELLENT PLACE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
OF COURSE.
I'M GLAD IT'S HERE.
KILLER FOOD,
GREAT ENERGY,
A GREAT STORY,
AND I'M TELLIN' YOU,
LEARNED A TON.
AWESOME, MAN.
THAT'S GREAT.
NICE.
APPRECIATE IT.
NEXT STOP, WE'RE HEADING
TO ST. PETERSBURG, FLORIDA...
CONSISTENTLY GOOD
COMFORT FOOD.
FOR A NEW TAKE...
(Guy) I LIKE THIS.
ON AN OLD DINER CLASSIC.
(man) TEXAS HASH.
MMM, THAT'S LEGIT HASH.
♪♪
I'M HERE IN BEAUTIFUL,
SUNNY ST. PETERSBURG, FLORIDA.
LOVE COMIN' HERE ON TRIPLE "D."
WELL, THIS PLACE
WE'RE ABOUT TO VISIT
OPENED IN 1952
AS A SUNDRIES SHOP--
YOU KNOW,
A CONVENIENCE STORE.
IT SOLD MILK AND EGGS
AND EVEN RENTED VACUUM CLEANERS.
THEY EVEN HAD A POST OFFICE.
WELL, AS TIMES CHANGE,
THE OWNERS REALIZED
THEY HAD TO CHANGE,
SO THEY ADDED ON A RESTAURANT.
THIS IS MUNCH'S RESTAURANT
AND SUNDRIES.
(man) CHICKEN READY.
GOOD, DOWN-HOME
COOKIN'.
MEAT LOAF.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
STICK-TO-YOUR-RIBS KIND OF FOOD.
THE KIND OF FOOD...
GOOD CHOICE.
LARRY MUNCH'S PARENTS STARTED
SERVING HERE IN THE '60s.
AND WE BUILT THE KITCHEN ON
AND ADDED THIS DINING ROOM ON.
AND WHEN LARRY TOOK OVER
IN '94...
YOU GOT YOUR
CHIPPED BEEF TODAY.
HE DIDN'T CHANGE MUCH.
BUT HE DID BRING IN
A FIRST-RATE CHEF...
(man) SHRIMP AND GRITS.
ST. PETE NATIVE
ERIC HARVEY...
GRILLED PORK CHOP.
WHO'S PUTTIN' THE MUNCH'S SPIN
ON DINER CLASSICS...
MUNCH BURGER
WITH CHEESE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
LIKE THIS TOP SELLER...
(Eric) TEXAS HASH.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
WITH SWEET SMOKED CHICKEN
INSTEAD OF BEEF.
IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
SHOW ME YOUR MAGIC.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH THE MUNCH'S RUB.
CAYENNE PEPPER,
OREGANO, CUMIN.
WE'LL GO WITH BROWN SUGAR,
A LITTLE SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
WHO MADE THIS RUB UP?
I DID.
PAPRIKA, CHILI POWDER.
GARLIC SALT.
GO AHEAD AND GET THIS
MIXED UP.
OKAY.
WE'RE READY
TO RUB-A-DUB.
RUB-A-DUB, CHICKEN'S
GOING IN THE TUB.
OKAY, MUNCH'S RUB--
GENEROUS WITH THAT.
NOW TOSS.
OKAY.
OKAY, WE'RE LOOKIN' GOOD.
WE'LL TAKE IT TO THE SMOKER.
NICE-LOOKIN'
SMOKER.
GOIN' ON
WITH THE CHICKEN.
SO IT'S NICE WHEN YOU GRILL
AND PUT SOME SMOKE TO IT.
WHAT KIND OF HARDWOOD
YOU USIN'?
FLORIDA OAK.
WE'RE NOT JUST USIN' OAK.
WE'RE USIN'...
(both) FLORIDA OAK.
HOW MANY HOURS?
I'D SAY AN HOUR AND A HALF,
TWO HOURS.
IN THAT 225 RANGE?
SHE'S ALL READY.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
I GOT THE LID.
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE
MAKIN' NEXT, BROTHER?
HOMEMADE BUTTERMILK
BISCUITS.
SIFTED FLOUR, BAKING SODA,
SALT, BAKING POWDER.
ALL RIGHTY.
BUTTER.
CHILLED BUTTER?
CHILLED BUTTER.
SWEET BUTTER.
SWEET,
CHILLED BUTTER.
I LIKE IT.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
MASH ALL THIS TOGETHER
UNTIL IT CRUMBLES.
BUTTERMILK.
YOU JUST WANT TO GET IT
MIXED TOGETHER, AND THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ALL.
SEE THAT? OKAY.
WE'LL FLOUR THE TABLE.
WOW, THIS IS BARELY
HOLDING TOGETHER.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO KNEAD THIS.
NOT AT ALL, MAN.
I CAN CUT.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
YOU ARE ONE EFFICIENT CAT.
IS HE GONNA MAKE 12?
COME ON.
WOW.
OLEO.
YOU'RE A MACHINE.
POP 'EM
IN THE OVEN.
325 AT, UH,
25 MINUTES.
NOW WE START PUTTIN'
THE HASH TOGETHER.
YES, SIR.
SO WE GOT THE CHICKEN.
TEAR IT OFF THE BONE.
I GIVE IT
A ROUGH CHOP.
DIG IT.
THE CHICKEN, SAUTéED PEPPERS,
ONIONS, AND GARLIC,
POTATOES.
WE GOT THE BISCUIT
ALL GROUND UP.
SO WHEN A BISCUIT GETS
A LITTLE DRIED OUT AND OLD...
I TAKE 'EM
TO THE ROBOT COUPE.
SEASON SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
TABASCO, AND DRIED PARSLEY.
OKAY, NOW YOU MASH
AND GRIND?
GET YOUR HANDS
IN THERE.
I LIKE THIS.
GENEROUS AMOUNT. MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING IS NICE AND TIGHT.
PATTY, PAPER--
NICE AND GENTLY. ALL RIGHT.
REALLY?
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
OKAY, WE'RE GOING ON THE GRILL
WITH THE TEXAS HASH.
I MEAN, EVERYTHING'S
COOKED IN THAT,
SO YOU JUST GOTTA LET IT
CRISP ON BOTH SIDES?
YES, SIR.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THESE
BUTTERMILK BISCUITS
OUT OF THE OVEN.
NICE.
COME OVER
TO THE TEXAS HASH.
THAT'S A FATTY PATTY.
OKAY.
LOOKIN' GOOD,
MY FRIEND.
MMM. WOW,
THIS IS AWESOME.
YOU GET A NICE AMOUNT
OF CHICKEN IN THERE.
THIN, AND IT'S GOT
A GOOD CRUST TO IT. MMM.
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
THAT'S LEGIT HASH.
A LITTLE BIT OF NICE
FLAKY BISCUIT. MMM.
YOU DO A GOOD JOB, MAN.
ACTUALLY, YOU DO A GREAT JOB.
OH, I APPRECIATE IT.
WHEN I COME BACK
TO ST. PETERSBURG,
I'M GONNA BE LOOKI''
FOR THAT.
(woman) TEXAS HASH.
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
THAN ANY KIND OF HASH
THAT YOU MIGHT
HAVE HAD.
THE BISCUITS ARE
VERY FLAVORFUL.
IT'S VERY TASTY.
(Eric) POTATOES.
MMM, IT'S ALL GOOD.
NICE. FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
WELL, WE COME IN
FOR BREAKFAST A LOT.
VEGGIE OMELET
IN THE WINDOW, PLEASE.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
THE "CHEERS"
OF THE BREAKFAST-LUNCH
RESTAURANTS.
GEORGE,
YOUR FAVORITE.
IT'S A REAL
COMMUNITY SPOT.
IT IS.
WITH THE PICTURES
TO PROVE IT.
THESE ARE ALL FROM
LAKEWOOD ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WHICH IS RIGHT DOWN
THE STREET.
SO YOU KNOW SOME
OF THESE PEOPLE.
I KNOW SOME
IT'S A VERY NOSTALGIC
RESTAURANT.
WITH A VERY
NOSTALGIC MENU.
(Eric) GRILLED
PORK CHOPS.
A DISH THEY'VE BEEN
CRANKIN' OUT FOR 50 YEARS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
WE HAVE A BONELESS,
CENTER-CUT PORK LOIN.
OKAY.
AND WE'RE GONNA JUST TAKE AWAY
SOME OF THIS FAT.
SO YOU TRIM THIS
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
CUT IT LIKE THIS.
I BUTTERFLY IT.
THAT'S A GOOD CHOP.
OH, YEAH.
POUND IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT. OKAY.
RIGHT.
I LIKE IT. SO LET'S
GET THIS THING RUBBED.
ALL RIGHT. MUNCH'S RUB. WE'RE
JUST GONNA BE GENEROUS AND EVEN.
NOW WE GO
TO THE FLAT TOP.
YES, SIR.
NICE.
GO WITH THE WEIGHT.
OKAY, THAT'S GONNA COOK
ABOUT TWO, THREE MINUTES
EACH SIDE?
YES, SIR. OKAY.
WE'LL GO TO THE PLATE.
GOOD-LOOKIN' COLOR ON THAT.
GOOD OL' COMFORT FOOD. MMM.
NICE JOB. GOOD JOB.
HAND-CUT, HAND-SEASONED,
FRESHLY COOKED CHOP.
JUST WATCH THAT.
THAT'S A REAL JUICY CHOP.
MAKE THE MASH,
MAKE THE GRAVY
ALL YOURSELF? MMM.
YES, SIR.
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
THAT'S ABOUT $7.25.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU WHAT,
THE LINE STARTS AT THE DOOR.
NICE JOB, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
(woman) PORK CHOP.
THEY'RE VERY TENDER,
SPICED JUST RIGHT.
SEASONED BEAUTIFULLY.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
(Eric) FRIED CHICKEN.
EVERYTHING TASTES GREAT.
IT'S A CONSISTENTLY GOOD
COMFORT FOOD.
(woman)
A LITTLE COLLARD GREEN.
STUFF THAT HAS SUBSTANCE
TO IT, YOU KNOW?
MEAT LOAF, BURGERS.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK...
(woman) CHIPPED BEEF.
MUNCH'S STYLE.
THE BEEF IS SO TENDER.
THAT'D BE GOOD.
♪♪
WELCOME BACK TO MUNCH'S
IN ST. PETERSBURG, FLORIDA.
ALL RIGHT, MY FRIEND,
ERIC, WHAT ARE WE COOKIN' NEXT?
WE'RE MAKIN' CREAMED
CHIPPED BEEF.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY FLAVORFUL,
REALLY GOOD.
THE BEEF IS SO TENDER.
(Guy)
CHIPPED BEEF.
HOW DO WE START?
WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH THE SEASONINGS HERE.
SALT, THYME, SEASON SALT,
GARLIC SALT,
AND BLACK PEPPER.
OKEYDOKE.
MIX THAT UP,
HIT IT ON THAT TOP ROUND.
THAT'S A BIG CHUNK OF MEAT.
LIBERALLY SEASON THAT.
AND THEN WHAT'S GONNA
HAPPEN HERE?
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER
TO MAKE MY DRIPPINGS.
OKAY, SO YOU LET
THAT WATER GET UNDERNEATH.
FOIL THIS LIKE A PILOT
PACKING HIS BAGS FOR FLIGHT.
COOK IT OFF IN THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP?
450.
FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR AND A HALF?
ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
IT COMES OUT, COOLS DOWN.
SLICE IT UP?
YES, SIR.
HIT IT. OKAY.
TRIM SOME OF THAT FAT.
WE'RE GONNA JULIENNE THIS.
JUST HALVE IT.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE WE
INTO NEXT, BOSS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CREAM SAUCE.
ROLL IT.
SWEET BUTTER.
(whistles)
ONIONS TO KICK THAT
UP A LITTLE BIT.
FLOUR. BASICALLY
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A ROUX.
LET THAT COME TOGETHER.
SOME BEEF DRIPPINGS.
NICE.
THIS IS WHERE A LOT OF FLAVOR
IS RIGHT HERE.
OKAY.
THEN YOU WANT TO COME
WITH WHITE PEPPER, SALT,
A LITTLE GARLIC SALT,
AND LET'S GET THAT IN.
TIGHT RIGHT NOW.
NOW WE'RE COMING
WITH THE HEAVY CREAM.
THIS WILL COME UP PRETTY FAST,
SO YOU WANNA KEEP WHISKIN' IT.
YOU NEVER WENT
TO CULINARY SCHOOL?
NO.
I JUST HAD A CHANCE TO WORK
WITH SOME GREAT CHEFS
THAT TOOK THE TIME OUT
TO REALLY TEACH ME
THE PROPER WAY.
IT'S GREAT, MAN.
LET IT THICKEN.
FRESH GARLIC?
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC.
THEN LAST WE HAVE
THE ROUND OF BEEF.
SO THAT'S GONNA GIVE
SOME OF ITS FLAVOR.
IT'S GONNA WARM UP
IN THERE.
OKAY, SHE'S DONE.
GOOD TO GO.
WE'RE GONNA LADLE THIS
RIGHT OVER WHITE TOAST.
BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
CREAMED CHIPPED BEEF.
THERE YOU GO. MMM.
THAT IS SOME
GOOD CHIPPED BEEF.
THAT TOUCH OF GARLIC AT THE END
GIVES IT NICE LITTLE BITE.
OH. STICK TO YOUR RIBS. MMM.
BROTHER, I'M TELLIN' YOU WHAT...
DOWN HOME.
DOWN HOME, UPTOWN--
YOU KNOCKED THIS OUT. MMM.
THAT IS MONEY.
CASH MONEY.
MMM. I'D EAT THAT
ALL DAY LONG.
CHIPPED BEEF.
CHIPPED BEEF
IS DELICIOUS.
GOOD STUFF,
ISN'T IT?
IT IS AWESOME.
THERE'S BEEF
IN EVERY BITE.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
CREAM SAUCE
IS VERY NICE.
(woman) THE SHRIMP
AND GRITS.
THIS ROCKS IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
GREATEST PLACE.
(Eric)
CAJUN CHICKEN.
OH, I LOVE THIS PLACE.
FRIED CHICKEN.
LOVE THE FOOD,
LOVE THE PEOPLE.
NICE JOB.
ACTUALLY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE IN THE KREW NOW.
ERIC'S IN THE HOUSE.
GO BIG OR GO HOME.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LET'S SEE IF WE CAN
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
(loud smack)