HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LOOK AT THOSE, HUH?
IT'S ALL HANDS ON DECK...
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
FOR SOME ALL-STAR SANDWICHES.
MMM.
TOP-NOTCH. THIS JUST PUTS
A WHOLE NEW DEFINITION
ON "FINGER LICKIN' GOOD."
IN SAN ANTONIO...
PICK-UP, PUFFY TACO.
IT'S FLUFFY, PUFFY,
AND YOU CAN'T GET ENOUGHY.
OHH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
THE TACO JOINT SO GOOD,
THEY HAD TO NAME IT TWICE.
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
A BARBECUE HANGOUT...
BURNT ENDS SANDWICH.
WHERE BURNT IS BEST...
MMM. LOOK AT THAT
BIG SMOKE RING ON THAT.
HEY, LOOK,
WHAT'S THAT OVER THERE?
AND IN CHICAGO, ILLINOIS,
A BURGER BAR
WHERE ALL KINDS OF FLAVORS...
TWO BISON
IN THE WINDOW.
ARE HITTIN' THE GRILL.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S CALLED CRUSTIFICATION.
THERE'S NOTHING
I WOULD CHANGE. AWESOME.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I LOVE THE NAMES
OF THE RESTAURANTS
WE VISIT ON TRIPLE "D."
I MEAN, SOMETIMES IT TALKS ABOUT
THE KIND OF FOOD THEY MAKE
OR WHO THEY ARE
OR WHERE THEY'RE FROM,
AND SOMETIMES,
IT JUST IS WHAT IT IS.
THE NAME SOUNDS COOL,
LIKE POK POK
OR NIKO NIKO'S
OR TAP TAP,
OR HERE IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
WHERE THEY'RE SERVIN' UP
SOME RIGHTEOUS MEXICAN FOOD,
THIS IS TACO TACO.
PICK-UP NORTENO.
THANK YOU.
THIS JOINT HAS
MEXICAN FLAVOR TO IT.
THE REAL DEAL
MEXICAN FLAVOR.
THE REAL DEAL.
BUT GET THIS...
TACO TACO SOUP.
ARE YOU LATINO?
NO, I'M GREEK.
AND OWNER HELEN VELESIOTIS...
STEAK RANCHERO.
TAUGHT HERSELF
TRADITIONAL MEXICAN COOKIN'...
ONE MINUTE ON PUFFY TACO.
AFTER DOIN' A LITTLE
OF EVERYTHING ELSE.
SEAFOOD, BARBECUE,
ITALIAN FOOD.
YOU DID ALL OF THAT?
YES, SIR.
AND WHEN SHE LANDED
IN SAN ANTONIO...
I FIGURE, I'M GONNA
DO MEXICAN FOOD.
A GREEK FAMILY
MAKIN' TACOS IN TEXAS.
HERE'S YOUR BEEF
CRISPY TACO.
WE LOVE IT.
WE COME HERE FOR A TACO FIX.
CARNE ASADA TACO.
UM, JUST
AN EXCELLENT TACO.
HERE'S A NORTENO READY.
THAT'S A MEAL,
RIGHT THERE.
PICK-UP, PUFFY TACO.
IT'S A STAPLE
IN SAN ANTONIO.
A PUFFY TACO IS
A TACO ON STEROIDS.
IT'S FLUFFY, PUFFY,
AND YOU CAN'T GET ENOUGHY.
SO WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO MAKE NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SHREDDED CHICKEN.
YES.
AND THAT GOES
ON THE WHAT?
ON THE PUFFY TACO.
OKAY.
SOME WATER,
THE CHICKEN--
THIGHS, HUH?
YEAH, CHICKEN THIGHS.
THAT'S A POULTRY
HOT TUB.
YES. WE'RE GONNA LET IT BOIL
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
LET IT BREAK DOWN.
AND GET SOFT.
NOW WHAT GOES IN?
FIRST, CHICKEN BASE.
GOT IT.
CUMIN AND THEN
FRESH GARLIC,
A LITTLE SALT.
OKAY.
LET IT COOK, THEN
WE'RE GONNA PUT ONIONS...
OKAY.
CELERY.
SWEET, THERE,
WITH SOME TOPS.
OUR PEPPERS, TOMATOES.
BEAUTIFUL.
GIVE IT A STIR?
YES.
THAT CHICKEN IS
BREAKIN' DOWN, HUH?
YES.
AND SOME TOMATO SAUCE.
BRINGS A LITTLE SWEETNESS.
AND SOME GREAT COLOR.
YES. AND LET IT COOK
ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
GONNA COME OUT
DELICIOSO.
BEAUTIFUL. OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
TORTILLAS.
CORN TORTILLAS.
GO AHEAD.
SOME CORN FLOUR--MASECA.
MASECA, DRY MASA.
AND THEN SOME SUGAR.
A LITTLE SALT.
SALT, A LITTLE
MANTEQUILLA, BUTTER.
WAY TO GET ALL SPANISH WITH ME
WITH THE MANTEQUILLA.
JUST A LITTLE WATER,
A LITTLE AT A TIME.
YES.
YOU GO OVER
AND IT'S TOO WET,
ADDING MORE MASA BACK IN
IS A TOTAL PAIN.
AND YOU MAKE ALL
OF THE MASA DOUGH BY HAND?
YES.
EVERY DAY.
YOU SHOULD TAKE UP
ARM WRESTLING.
WE'RE DONE.
DO WE HAVE
ENOUGH MASA?
YES.
SO NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
NOW WE'RE GONNA
GO FLATTEN THEM
AND MAKE 'EM TORTILLAS.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
FIRST YOU MAKE
A LITTLE BALL.
YOU'RE GONNA
FLATTEN ONE, OKAY.
THIS LITTLE FRYER.
YES.
375 DEGREES.
YES, GOTTA BE HOT.
THIS GETS PUFFY, NO?
BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH.
A LITTLE BIT ON THE TOP,
AND THEN WE GO SLOWLY DOWN.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK
FOR A TACO.
AND A TASTY TACO.
OKAY, THAT'S OUR PUFFY.
PUFFY THE MAGIC TACO.
WE'RE GONNA FILL IT
WITH SHREDDED CHICKEN,
SOME LETTUCE, TOMATOES,
SHREDDED CHEESE,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF GUACAMOLE
FOR A LITTLE EXTRA FLAVOR.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
MMM, THAT'S NICE.
PUFFY RIDICULOUS.
THE TACO'S GOT GOOD CRUNCH,
BUT IT'S NICE AND SOFT.
OH, THE CHICKEN'S GOT
LOTS OF FLAVOR.
YOU GIVE A HUGE PORTION.
MMM. YOU KNOW WHAT YOU SHOULD
NAME THIS PLACE?
TACO TACO CAFé.
THAT'S A GREAT NAME.
IT'S SO NICE,
THEY NAMED IT TWICE.
SHE WINS.
GOOD JOB.
PUFFY TACO.
THE SHELL IS EXCELLENT.
PUFFED UP, WARM--
TORTILLA'S FABULOUS.
PERFECTLY SEASONED--
IT GIVES YOU
A NICE FULL FEELING.
IT STICKS WITH YOU.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU IS GREAT.
YOU MAKE ALMOST
EVERYTHING YOURSELF.
EVERYTHING MYSELF,
EVERYTHING HANDMADE.
AND SHE'S EVEN SCRATCH-MAKIN'
HER FAMOUS FLOUR TORTILLAS
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE BOLITAS
OUT OF THIS.
BOLITAS.
YES, THEY'RE LITTLE BALLS.
YES.
GONNA MAKE LIKE THIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA OPEN
THE TORTILLAS.
EACH ONE BY HAND.
AND HOW MANY A DAY?
1,000, 2,000,
IT DEPENDS ON THE DAY.
(mouthing words)
WE'VE ALREADY MADE TWO,
I'M TIRED.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM, OHH, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
THE TORTILLAS--OHH.
YOU JUST CAN'T GO WRONG.
EVEN WHEN LOADED...
TACO DE LENGUA.
WITH THIS.
LENGUA IS BEEF TONGUE--
VERY LEAN, SO IT'S
KIND OF LIKE A ROAST.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS
VERY HONESTLY.
OKAY.
I HAVE NOT HAD
MUCH TONGUE THAT I'VE LIKED.
I'M DOIN' THIS BECAUSE I SAW
LENGUA ON THE MENU,
AND IT'S TIME
TO LIKE THE LENGUA.
ARE YOU READY?
(whispering)
WHY DO I DO THIS TO MYSELF?
(normal voice) OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA
BOIL THEM FIRST.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE LENGUA--
I BET I AM NOT GONNA.
WE BOILED 'EM,
AND THEY'VE COOLED.
NOW YOU SKIN THE TONGUE.
YES.
LOOK HOW EASY.
OHH, LOOK AT THAT.
START CUTTING INTO CUBES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA...
SAUTé.
A LITTLE OIL.
OKAY, YOU'RE GONNA
SHOVEL IN THE LENGUA.
YES.
THIS JUST PUTS
A WHOLE NEW DEFINITION
ON "FINGER LICKIN' GOOD,"
DOESN'T IT?
YES.
WE'RE GONNA BROWN IT
A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN WE PUT...
ONIONS.
TOMATOES, JALAPEÑOS.
OKAY, THAT'S A LOT
OF JALAPEÑOS.
YOU DON'T EVEN FEEL THE HEAT.
THE LENGUA TAKES IT AWAY.
JUST LICKS THE FLAME.
YES, OF COURSE.
A LITTLE BEEF PASTE,
FRESH GARLIC.
OH, I LIKE THAT.
A LITTLE CUMINO.
CUMIN, SALT,
TOMATO SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA STIR IT.
(whispering) THERE'S A LOT
OF TONGUE IN THERE.
I'M A DEAD MAN.
(normal voice) THIS IS GONNA
COOK DOWN FOR ABOUT A YEAR?
IT ONLY NEEDS 30 MINUTES.
PRAY THAT IT
BREAKS DOWN MORE,
'CAUSE THERE'S BIG CHUNKS...
OF TONGUE.
WE'RE DOIN' IT NOW,
AREN'T WE?
YES, WE'RE DOIN' IT.
WE'RE GONNA GET
THE LENGUA GOIN', EH?
IT'S GONNA BE SO GOOD.
THE LETTUCE, TOMATOES.
THIS, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS STRAIGHT-UP, DOWNTOWN,
IN-YOUR-FACE LENGUA.
BECAUSE YOU MADE IT,
I'M GOIN' AFTER IT.
PLEASE HELP ME, PLEASE
HELP ME, PLEASE HELP ME.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S DEFINITELY GOT
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
HONESTLY, IF YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
THAT IT WAS LENGUA,
I WOULDN'T EVEN KNOW.
THIS IS COOKED SO WELL--
YOU MIGHT HAVE CONVERTED ME
TO LENGUA FOREVER NOW. MMM.
THERE'S A REAL RICH
FLAVOR TO IT.
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
SHE'S A SUPERSTAR.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR LENGUA.
THANK YOU. IT'S SO TENDER,
IT'S ALMOST LIKE EATING
BEEF STEW. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
IT MELTS IN MY MOUTH.
LOVE IT.
PLATE IS READY.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
I THINK THE CARE THAT
THEY PUT INTO THEIR FOOD
MAKES IT STAND OUT.
MENUDO FOR TABLE 10.
THERE ARE MILLIONS OF MEXICAN
RESTAURANTS IN SAN ANTONIO,
BUT THIS IS ONE I COME BACK TO.
NOW WE WANT YOU BACK.
I'LL BE BACK.
LET'S MAKE A PLAN.
I'M GONNA WAIT FOR YOU.
IT'S A DATE.
YOU GOTTA COME SEE
THIS GIRL.
UP NEXT...
CHECK THIS OUT.
WE'RE HEADED
TO VIRGINIA BEACH...
DELICIOUS.
FOR A KANSAS CITY CLASSIC...
BURNT ENDS SANDWICH.
THE BARBECUE REMINDS ME OF HOME.
AND THANKSGIVING ON A BUN.
THAT IS A RIGHTEOUS
TURKEY SANDWICH, MAN.
I'LL TAKE 3,000 OF THEM
TO GO, PLEASE.
I'M HERE IN
VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
ABOUT 10 MILES SOUTH
OF THE CHESAPEAKE BAY
AND ABOUT 10 MILES WEST
OF THE ATLANTIC OCEAN.
NOW I'VE BEEN
THROUGH HERE BEFORE
AND HAD EVERYTHING FROM SEAFOOD
TO HOMEMADE ICE CREAM CONES,
BUT WHEN I HEAR THERE'S A DUDE
THAT'S KNOCKIN' OUT BURNT ENDS,
NORTH CAROLINA PULLED PORK,
AND SMOKED TURKEY,
WELL, YOU KNOW
I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS WHITNER'S BARBECUE.
PULLED PORK PLATTER WITH
BAKED BEANS AND GREEN BEANS.
I LOVE IT--
SOUTHERN STYLE BARBECUE.
AND THEN SOME.
THE BRISKET IS AWESOME.
IT REMINDS ME OF TEXAS.
THE ST. LOUIS CUT RIBS--
MY FAVORITE MEAL HERE.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
'CAUSE OWNER WARREN ROGERS...
BURNT ENDS SANDWICH.
STARTED YOUNG.
RAISED ON BARBECUE.
BUT IT WAS ONLY A HOBBY
TILL TWO YEARS AGO...
ALL RIGHT.
WHEN WARREN AND HIS
BROTHER-IN-LAW CHRIS JANOWSKI
DECIDED TO TAKE THE PLUNGE...
IT WAS SINK OR SWIM.
IT WAS A CAREER CHANGE FOR ME.
CHOP THE 401(k).
YOU GOT IT.
AND STARTED CRANKIN' OUT
THE 'CUE.
BRISKET PLATTER.
WHAT MAKES GOOD BARBECUE?
IT'S GOTTA BE THE MEAT,
NUMBER ONE, BEIN' FRESH,
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
IT'S THE SEASONING.
THAT'D BE THE HOUSE RUB
THAT'S GOIN' ON THIS
KANSAS CITY CLASSIC.
BURNT ENDS SANDWICH.
OUTSTANDING.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
ALL RIGHT, MR. WHITNER'S
BARBECUE RUB.
OKAY.
PAPRIKA.
WAIT A SECOND.
YOU GOTTA--THERE YOU GO.
CHILI POWDER,
BROWN SUGAR,
PEPPER, GROUND CELERY...
GOOD-LOOKIN' RUB.
SALT, GROUND MUSTARD...
(whistles)
CAYENNE.
AND A LITTLE
GRANULATED GARLIC.
THOSE ALL MIXED UP--
THAT'S GOOD TO GO.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE MAKI''
THE BEEF.
YOU GOT IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME BARBECUE RUB...
A LOT OF SALT.
AND THEN WE GO
WITH THE BROWN SUGAR
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
AND THAT'S IT.
YOU GOT IT.
AND HIT THIS
ALL OVER THE BRISKET?
WHAT I LIKE TO DO IS
MAKE SURE IT GETS A GOOD COAT
ALL THE WAY AROUND, AND LET THAT
SEASONING WORK ITS WAY DOWN.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA GRAB
A COUPLE MORE
AND PUT 'EM IN THE SMOKER.
AT WHAT TEMP?
200.
FOR HOW MANY HOURS?
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
12, 12, YEP.
12, NICE.
OKAY, WHAT SAUCE
ARE WE MAKIN'?
SWEET SAUCE.
SO GET ME STARTED.
A LITTLE WHITE VINEGAR...
OH, THAT'LL
CLEAR YOU OUT.
CIDER VINEGAR...
OKAY, A LITTLE
CHILI POWDER.
PEPPER.
TOO TALL
TO BE DOIN' THAT JOB.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
GROUND MUSTARD...
GRANULATED GARLIC.
SOME ONION POWDER,
WHITNER'S BARBECUE RUB,
GROUND CELERY,
SALT...
MESS OF SALT.
AND BROWN SUGAR.
MAN.
THANK GOODNESS YOU GOT
YOURSELF A BIG OL' KETTLE.
YOU GOT IT.
SO WE GOT THIS ALL MIXED IN.
WHAT'S NEXT?
SOME PINEAPPLE JUICE...
AND MORE PINEAPPLE JUICE.
YEAH.
NICE NATURAL SWEETENER.
MORE CIDER VINEGAR?
YEP, GOTTA GET THAT TANG.
WU-TANG.
THERE YOU GO.
BIG WU-TANG CLAN FAN
OVER HERE.
(laughing)
SOME WORCESTERSHIRE.
(whistles)
A GALLON OF MUSTARD.
YOU GOT IT.
HOT SAUCE.
TOMATO PASTE.
A BUNCH OF GOODNESS,
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S LAKE BARBECUE SAUCE,
OVER IN FLAVOR TOWN.
YEP, AND WE GOT
SOME CHIPOTLE SAUCE,
AND THEN WE GET
SOME WATER IN THERE.
OKAY.
SO HOW LONG DO YOU
LET THIS SIMMER?
TILL EVERYTHING
GETS DISSOLVED.
THEN WHEN IT'S DONE,
YOU JUST CRANK IT,
POURS RIGHT OUT
IN THE BUCKET.
YOU GOT IT.
AWESOME. OKAY.
NOW'S THE GOOD PART.
(whistles)
CHECK THIS OUT.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE
ALL THE FAT OFF IT.
YEAH. ON THE BURNT ENDS,
YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
THAT EXTRA FAT IN THERE.
SLICE IT INTO CUBES...
YOU GOT IT.
HIT IT WITH SAUCE.
YES.
THAT SAUCE IS RIGHTEOUS.
ALL RIGHT, GONNA PUT THIS BABY
UNDER SOME FOIL.
WE THROW IT
BACK IN THE OVEN.
OVEN AT 350?
YOU GOT IT,
A GOOD 45 MINUTES.
OKAY.
LET'S GO TO THE OVEN
AND GET THOSE BURNT ENDS.
JUST PEEL THIS BABY
BACK, ALL RIGHT.
THIS COOKED IT DOWN AND THEN
JUST ABSORBED THE SAUCE--
LOOK AT THAT BIG
SMOKE RING ON THAT.
THAT'S HOW SHE GOES.
MMM.
GOOD BEEF, NICE RUB,
GOOD SMOKE.
IT'S VERY RICH. MMM.
SAUCE GOT A LITTLE SWEET,
A LITTLE HEAT, A LOT OF VINEGAR,
THEN YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT WORCESTERSHIRE IN THE BACK.
NICE JOB,
REALLY NICE JOB.
THANK YOU,
I APPRECIATE IT.
HEY, LOOK,
WHAT'S THAT OVER THERE?
(Warren) GOT A BURNT ENDS
SANDWICH COMIN' UP.
THEY'RE JUST DELICIOUS.
THE SAUCE COMPLEMENTS THE MEAT.
TENDER, GOOD FLAVOR--VERY GOOD.
HERE IT IS,
SIDE DISH PLATTER.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
WITH HOMEMADE SIDES,
LIKE POTATO SALAD
AND DIRTY RICE...
SORT OF LIKE
MY MOTHER COOKING IT.
RIGHT DOWN TO A HOLIDAY DINNER
EVERY DAY.
MR. WHITNER'S SMOKED TURKEY.
LIKE A THANKSGIVING MEAL
IN A BUN.
WITH CRANBERRY CHUTNEY
AND CORNBREAD CROUTONS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
TURKEY TIME.
YOU GOT IT. THIS IS
THE TURKEY BREAST
FOR THE MR. WHITNER'S
SMOKED TURKEY.
OKAY.
WE START OFF, CANOLA OIL,
AND JUST PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT ON THERE,
RUB THAT IN.
AND SOME OF
THE BARBECUE RUB WE MADE?
YES, RUB OUR
TURKEY BREAST.
AND NOW WE GO
TO THE SMOKER?
DOES IT STAY ON THE TRAY
OR DOES IT GO ON A RACK?
WE LEAVE THIS ON THE TRAY.
READY TO ROLL?
YEP, OFF TO THE SMOKER.
ALL RIGHT.
AND WHAT ARE WE
SMOKIN' WITH?
HICKORY WOOD.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
GOT SOME TURKEY.
LOOK AT THAT. HOW LONG
WAS THAT DOWN?
A COUPLE HOURS.
WE'RE GONNA SLICE
THIS TURKEY.
MMM.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO THANKSGIVING
AT MY HOUSE ANYTIME.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S THE CHUTNEY
WITH CRANBERRIES THERE.
YEP.
THIS IS A SPICY MAYO.
BASICALLY, IT'S A CURRY,
SOME HABANERO MASH.
OKAY.
THE CORNBREAD CROUTON.
YOU CRUMBLE UP A CORNBREAD
CROUTON ON HERE?
YEP, NICE LITTLE CRUNCH.
AND THEN WE'LL GO AHEAD AND PUT
A LITTLE LETTUCE ON TOP THERE.
THERE YOU GO.
TAKE A LOOKY-LOO AT THAT.
NOW THAT RIGHT THERE--
THAT IS A RIGHTEOUS TURKEY
SANDWICH, MAN. TOP-NOTCH.
A LOT OF TURKEY,
SMOKED PERFECTLY.
THE CRANBERRY SAUCE
IS RIGHT THERE FOR THE TANG,
BUT YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THE CRAZY PART IS?
IT WAS THIS LITTLE CORNBREAD
CRUNCHY CRUNCH IN THERE.
IT'S LIKE PUTTIN' POTATO CHIPS
ON A SANDWICH
WHEN YOU WERE A KID.
I'LL TAKE 3,000 OF THEM
TO GO, PLEASE. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
MR. WHITNER'S
SMOKED TURKEY.
IT IS FABULOUS.
THE TURKEY IS FRESH, GOT A NICE
SMOKED FLAVOR TO IT.
41. THERE'S YOUR
BURNT ENDS SANDWICH.
THIS RESTAURANT
DOES EVERYTHING WELL.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU, WARREN,
YOU'RE ROCKIN' IT OUT, MAN.
APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
THANKS FOR HAVIN' ME, MAN.
UP NEXT...
NUMBER 5 BISON BURGER.
WE'RE HEADED
TO THE WINDY CITY...
IT'S A BURGER JOINT.
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE
A BURGER.
WHERE A STRAIGHT-UP
BURGER BAR...
THEY HAVE SUCH VARIETY.
SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
IS SERVIN' UP KILLER COMBOS.
AWESOME.
WAY TO GO, CHEF.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M ABOUT EIGHT BLOCKS SOUTH
OF THE FAMOUS WRIGLEY FIELD,
ON SHEFFIELD AVENUE.
NOW THIS IS THE AVENUE
WHERE EVERYBODY STANDS
WHEN SOMEONE HITS A HOME RUN AND
THEY GO RUNNIN' FOR THE BALL,
BUT WE'RE NOT HERE
TO TALK ABOUT BASEBALL.
WE'RE NOT EVEN HERE
TO TALK ABOUT CHICAGO DOGS.
WE'RE HERE TO TALK ABOUT
BURGERS THAT ARE RIGHT ON.
THIS IS DMK BURGER BAR.
SO MANY DIFFERENT
TYPES OF BURGERS.
TWO HAM UP.
THE JUICE IS JUST
ALL OVER MY PLATE.
BACON CHEDDAR
BARBECUE BURGER.
I LOVE EATIN' HERE.
I EAT HERE ALL THE TIME.
CRISPY PORTOBELLO.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE COMING HERE
AND EATING GOURMET.
'CAUSE GOURMET RESTAURANT VET
MICHAEL KORNICK
IS RUNNIN' THE GRILL.
IT'S SO MUCH MORE FUN
THAN FINE DINING.
GRAVY FRIES COMIN' UP.
SO IN THE FALL OF '09,
HE GOT TOGETHER
WITH FRIEND DAVID MORTON
TO BRAND THEIR OWN BURGER BAR.
SO DMK--
THERE WAS A LACK
OF IMAGINATION.
REALLY?
'CAUSE THEY SAVED THAT
FOR THE BURGERS.
THEY GET YOU TO STEP OUT
OF YOUR ORDINARY BOUNDARIES,
GET YOU TO TRY SOMETHING NEW.
FROM A BURGER TOPPED WITH
GREEN CHILI AND A FRIED EGG...
IT'S AUTOMATIC.
SERIOUSLY, WITH AN EGG?
WITH AN EGG, FRIED EGG.
TO A PORTOBELLO
WITH DIJON AND BRIE.
I'VE NEVER HAD A BURGER
WITH A FRIED PORTOBELLO
MUSHROOM ON TOP. OUTRAGEOUS.
BUT THAT'S NOTHIN' COMPARED
TO THIS UNIQUE COMBO.
TWO BISON IN THE WINDOW.
BARBECUE BLUEBERRY SAUCE--
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE INTO, CHEF?
WE'RE MAKIN' OUR
BLUEBERRY BARBECUE SAUCE
FOR THE BISON BURGER.
OH, WAIT A SECOND.
SERIOUSLY?
BLUEBERRY BARBECUE SAUCE?
BLUEBERRY BARBECUE SAUCE.
IT'S--IT'S ONE
OF THOSE WEIRD THINGS
THAT'S JUST GOT ENOUGH
VINEGAR IN IT
TO KICK UP THE BISON
A NOTCH.
OKAY.
THAT'S IT. THAT'S ALL
I CAN TELL YOU.
WHY DID YOU JUST SOUND
LIKE CASEY KASEM?
I DON'T KNOW, I JUST--
(imitates Casey Kasem) TO KICK
UP THE BARBECUE SAUCE A NOTCH.
(normal voice)
SO SOME OLIVE OIL,
SOME RED ONION--
JALAPEÑO PEPPERS.
JUST LET THOSE COOK OFF
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
WE HAVE SOME DIJON MUSTARD,
KETCHUP, BROWN SUGAR,
RICE WINE VINEGAR, AND THEN
LOTS OF FRESH BLUEBERRIES.
SO ABOUT 50-50
ON THE BLUEBERRIES
TO EVERYTHING ELSE.
YEAH, AND THEN,
SOME TABASCO SAUCE.
WE LET IT COOK DOWN...
ABOUT A HALF-HOUR.
AND THEN WE BLEND IT
SO IT'S REAL SMOOTH,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
SO THE BARBECUE SAUCE
IS DONE.
NOW WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
WE'RE ON TO MAKING
THE BISON BURGER.
5 OUNCES OF BURGER.
THEY GO ON THE GRIDDLE,
GET SEASONED A LITTLE BIT.
NOW IS THIS AN 80-20?
THIS IS 85-15.
85--I WAS GONNA SAY,
IT'S BISON, IT'S A LITTLE
BIT MORE LEAN.
YEAH.
I LIKE THIS THING
THAT YOU DO HERE
WHERE YOU FLATTEN THIS OUT
A LITTLE BIT
AND YOU BUILD CRUST.
I LOVE THE CRUNCH.
YEAH.
WE'RE TRYIN' TO LITERALLY
SCRAPE THE BURGER--
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S CALLED CRUSTIFICATION.
IT KIND OF LOOKS
LIKE SAUSAGE LINKS
AND BURGER.
LOOK AT THOSE, HUH?
FRESH CALIFORNIA
GOAT CHEESE.
(whistles)
GOAT.
PRACTICALLY
THE WHOLE GOAT.
(laughing)
THE BLUEBERRY BARBECUE SAUCE,
AND IT GETS TOPPED
WITH SOME ONIONS
MARINATED IN VINEGAR.
WE TOP IT.
MMM.
LET ME JUST TAKE A MOMENT.
THIS IS MONSTER FLAVOR.
IT'S A LITTLE WEIRD,
BUT THEN IT COMES TOGETHER,
'CAUSE THE VINEGAR
AND THE ONIONS...
AND THE ONIONS.
AND IT JUMPS.
MMM.
YOU GET THE CRUNCHIFICATION
FROM THE CRUST OF THAT PATTY
AND THE BISON'S THE BOMB.
AWESOME. WAY TO GO, CHEF.
NUMBER 5 BISON BURGER.
YOU'VE GOT
THE BISON PATTY,
WHICH HAS, YOU KNOW,
A LITTLE MORE OF A BITE.
THE BLUEBERRY--I KIND OF LIKE
THE LITTLE SWEET KICK IT HAS.
IT'S RIGHT UP THERE
WITH THE OTHER BURGERS
I'VE HAD HERE--ALL GREAT.
SALMON BURGER.
THEY HAVE SUCH VARIETY.
SOMETHING FOR EVERYONE.
WHEN YOU STARTED
DESIGNING A BURGER MENU,
DID YOU FEEL THAT YOU HAD
A RESPONSIBILITY
TO TOUCH ALL SPECTRUMS?
IT'S A BURGER JOINT.
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE A BURGER.
AND HE'S GOT MORE THAN A DOZEN
ON THE MENU,
BUT "BURGER" DOESN'T HAVE
TO MEAN BEEF.
TRUFFLE FRIES
AND A TURKEY BURGER.
THEY'RE THE BEST TURKEY BURGER
YOU'LL EVER FIND.
THIS VEGGIE BURGER
IS FANTASTIC.
SALMON READY.
AND HE'S EVEN DOIN'
A SALMON BURGER,
TOPPED WITH HOMEMADE
ASIAN COLESLAW
AND RED THAI CURRY MAYO.
YOU DON'T OFTEN SEE
A SALMON BURGER ON A MENU.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THIS IS
A NICE-LOOKIN' PIECE.
WE'RE GONNA SLICE IT THIN
AND CUBE IT INTO...
LITTLE PIECES,
SO IT BINDS AS A BURGER.
A LITTLE GINGER.
A LITTLE SCALLION,
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF LEMON JUICE,
A COUPLE OF EGG YOLKS...
A LITTLE BINDER.
PANKO, PEPPER,
PINCH OF SALT,
SO ONCE THAT'S MIXED,
WE'RE GONNA SCOOP IT OUT,
IN THE BURGER RING,
WE PAT IT DOWN...
AIN'T NO THING
BUT A BURGER RING.
GIVE IT A LITTLE
PANKO ON TOP
AND A LITTLE PANKO
ON BOTTOM.
GO TO THE FLATTOP.
START WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF BUTTER DOWN,
BECAUSE THE SALMON BREADCRUMBS
WANT TO GET THAT,
AND WE ALSO GOT A BUN
THAT'S BEEN BUTTERED
WITH SWEET CREAM BUTTER,
AND WE'RE GONNA TOAST THAT.
SO WE LET THE BURGER GO.
WE GOT THE BUN TOASTIN'.
AND WE TURN IT.
WE'RE GONNA FINISH
THE BURGER.
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR
RED CURRY MAYONNAISE.
COPIOUS AMOUNTS.
LET ME SHOW YOU SOMETHING--
BUN MEETS PATTY SIZE.
THE KEY.
EVER SO CRITICAL.
ASIAN COLESLAW.
I LIKE THAT.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
COME ON.
THE CRUNCH OF THE SLAW--
I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW WHAT REALLY
TO HIGHLIGHT FOR YOU FIRST.
THE SALMON--SUPER TENDER.
PHENOMENAL CRUNCH
FROM THE PANKO.
YOU GET A LITTLE SPARKLE
OF THAT GINGER.
NICE LITTLE ACID COMIN' THROUGH
FROM THE CABBAGE.
THIS RIGHT HERE--I'D ORDER THIS
AGAIN IN A HEARTBEAT.
AWESOME JOB, CHEF, REALLY.
AWES--
NEXT.
HERE'S THE NUMBER 14
SALMON BURGER.
THE FISH IS AS GOOD
AS YOU CAN BUY.
THE SAUCE--IT IS FANTASTIC.
IT'S, UH, LITTLE BIT
BITE ON THE TONGUE,
A LITTLE BIT HAPPY TIME.
EVERYTHING IS WONDERFUL.
AND WAIT TILL YOU SEE HOW
THEY'RE KICKIN' UP THE FRIES.
NEXT WE'RE MAKIN'
TRUFFLE FRIES?
TRUFFLE FRIES.
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
AT DMK BURGER BAR IN CHICAGO...
LAMB BURGER AND CHEDDAR FRY.
I MEAN, THIS COULD BE
A FINE DINING RESTAURANT.
IT'S A REAL BURGER PLACE.
HEAD CHEF MICHAEL KORNICK IS
CRANKIN' OUT REAL DEAL BURGERS
AND HOMEMADE SIDES,
LIKE A TRUFFLE AIOLI
FOR THE FRIES.
LET'S GET THIS GOIN'.
TRUFFLE AIOLI.
COUPLE OF EGG YOLKS,
AND GET
THIS EMULSION RUNNING
WITH JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF THE LEMON JUICE,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA START
WITH VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
SO HOW OFTEN
ARE YOU DOIN' THE, UH...
WELL, WE DO A BIG BATCH
ONCE EVERY THREE DAYS.
BY HAND?
YEAH, BUT WE'VE GOT
A LOT OF GUYS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE WHITE TRUFFLE OIL,
AND YOU'LL SMELL IT AS SOON
AS IT HITS THE BOWL.
LOOK GOOD?
THAT'S PRETTY CLOSE.
A LITTLE SALT?
YEP.
ADD PEPPER.
SOME LEMON IN THAT.
YEAH, A LITTLE BIT.
AIOLI'S DONE,
TIME TO DO THE FRIES.
GIMME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
SOME IDAHO RUSSET POTATOES,
AND WE'LL HAVE 'EM
WELL-AGED BY OUR VENDOR.
INTERESTING.
WE'RE LOOKIN' FOR A POTATO
THAT'S BEEN AGED, YOU KNOW,
THREE OR FOUR MONTHS AT LEAST.
'CAUSE WE KNOW,
WHEN WE DON'T HAVE THAT,
WE END UP GETTING FRIES
THAT COOK TOO FAST,
BROWN UP TOO FAST, 'CAUSE
YOU'RE BURNIN' THE SUGARS,
AND THE FRY'S NOT REALLY COOKED
AND IT DOESN'T WORK.
WE PUT 'EM IN A FRENCH-FRY
CUTTER, 3/8-INCH CUT,
AND WE WASH 'EM,
THEN WE DRAIN 'EM.
SO THREE DIFFERENT FRYERS.
WE'RE BLANCHING 'EM
IN BEEF FAT.
DOWN AT 250, AND HOW LONG
WILL THEY GO?
THEY'LL GO ABOUT
FOUR MINUTES OR SO.
THE FRIES ARE BLANCHED.
LET 'EM HANG OUT
ON THE TRAY.
AND THEN THEY'RE FINISHED
IN BEEF FAT,
THREE MINUTES OR SO.
BUT YOU GOTTA BE
DELICATE WITH 'EM,
BECAUSE WHEN THEY'RE
THIS SOFT,
THEY CAN BREAK INTO A LOT
OF LITTLE PIECES...
RIGHT.
AND NO SITTIN' THERE
STIRRIN' 'EM WITH TONGS.
RIGHT.
TAKE 'EM TILL THEY'RE NICE
AND GOLDEN BROWN,
AND THEN AS SOON
AS THEY GO IN THE BOWL,
WHILE THEY'RE STILL
A LITTLE BIT WET,
WE WANT TO SEASON 'EM UP
WITH SALT,
PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT
OF PARMESAN CHEESE...
I LIKE IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY
FOR COLOR,
AND THEY GO ON
A LARGE PLATE,
THEY GET THEN SERVED WITH
THE TRUFFLE CREAM.
MMM. CRUNCHY EXTERIOR,
TENDER--SUCH A RICHNESS.
AND MORE IMPORTANTLY
TO ME THAN ANYTHING, SKIN ON.
SEE, I LIKE PEPPER
ON MY FRIES, TOO.
THE AIOLI--NICE.
IT MELTS
RIGHT INTO THE FRIES.
I MEAN, REAL DEAL, MAN.
REAL DEAL.
IF YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
A GOURMET BURGER JOINT,
YOU BETTER SERVE UP
A GOURMET FRY.
THAT'S IT, RIGHT?
EXCELLENT.
TRUFFLE FRY UP.
GREAT FRIES.
THEY'RE GREAT FRIES.
HERE ARE THE PARMESAN
TRUFFLE CREAM FRIES.
THEY'RE CRISPY, BUT THEY'RE
SOFT IN THE MIDDLE.
REAL POTATO TASTE.
THE TRUFFLE IS DELICIOUS.
THE CREAM IS KIND OF SWEET,
AND WITH THE CHEESE ON TOP OF
THE FRIES, IT'S KIND OF TANGY.
IT'S JUST A VERY RICH TASTE.
(man) IT'S DELICIOUS.
TWO SALMON BURGERS
GOIN' IN THE WINDOW.
EVERYTHING IS
REALLY WELL DONE HERE.
THIS IS THE NUMBER 5
BISON BURGER.
WE COME HERE PROBABLY
THREE TIMES A WEEK.
IT'S THE BEST.
IT'S THE BEST IN TOWN.
YOU'RE GETTIN' FOOD
THAT'S PREPARED HERE--
REAL DEAL,
HANDMADE BY PEOPLE
THAT YOU KNOW.
REAL DEAL.
I GOTTA TELL YOU SOMETHING.
YOU'RE A PHENOMENAL CHEF,
A GREAT ENTREPRENEUR...
THANKS.
AND ONE FUN CAT
TO COOK WITH.
THANKS SO MUCH.
THANKS FOR HAVIN' ME.
GOOD TIME, MAN.
THANKS FOR BEIN' HERE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE RECIPES
TO SOME OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(spoon clangs)
I THINK I WAS SHOT.
OH, NO.