HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MIYA!
I'M ROCKIN' TO THE BEAT...
WHOA!
OF SOME SERIOUS LATIN EATS.
THIS IS FAR BEYOND
TEX-MEX.
IN CHICAGO--
A FAMILY COSTA RICAN JOINT
KICKIN' UP THE CLASSICS.
(man) CHICHARRóN.
DUDE, THIS IS
BODY BY CHICHARRóN.
YEAH, BODY BY CHICHARRóN.
WHERE ARE YOU GONNA PUT
ALL THAT?
MMM. THE BOMB.
IN SAN ANTONIO...
(imitating car engine)
SHIFTING GEARS
FROM TYPICAL TEX-MEX...
THIS IS A UNIQUE RESTAURANT
FOR SAN ANTONIO.
INTO FLAVOR-FILLED
EMPANADAS...
NICE FLAKY CRUST.
AND CHALUPAS WITH A TWIST.
"WAKE UP AND KICK YOU IN
THE LUNCHBOX" ON THAT ONE. MMM.
AND IN QUEENS, NEW YORK...
TRY THIS.
WE'RE STACKING UP THE FLAVORS
OF MAINLAND MEXICO...
MEAT, PINEAPPLE, ONION.
AND TURNING OUT TORTILLAS
BY THE TON.
IT'S LIKE "LAVERNE & SHIRLEY"
MEETS LUCILLE BALL.
YEAH, THANKS. THANKS
FOR LEAVING ME A LITTLE BIT.
HMM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I DON'T THINK
IT'S ANY SURPRISE TO ANYONE
I'M A HUGE FAN OF LATIN CUISINE.
I MEAN, I'VE BEEN IN MEXICO
A BUNCH,
COOKED PUERTO RICAN, YOU KNOW,
SALVADORAN, CUBAN FOOD
ALL ON "GUY'S BIG BITE."
AND ANY CHANCE WE GET
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WELL, WE TRY TO VISIT
THE LATIN RESTAURANTS.
SO HERE WE ARE
IN BUCKTOWN, CHICAGO,
TO CHECK OUT WHAT MAY BE
A TRIPLE "D" FIRST--
A COSTA RICAN JOINT.
THIS IS IRAZU.
(woman) STEAK CASADO.
IRAZU IS AMAZING.
(man) CHICHARRóN
WITH FRIED YUCA.
IT REALLY JUST BRINGS
THE FLAVOR OF COSTA RICA
TO CHICAGO.
(woman) CHIFRIJO.
IT'S AMAZING.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(man) EMPANADAS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(woman) PICADILLO'S READY.
IT'S AN ECLECTIC,
INTERESTING MENU.
A MENU COSTA RICAN-BORN
MIRIAM CERDAS...
ALMOST READY, YOU GUYS.
CAME UP WITH
20 YEARS AGO.
TWO MINUTES MORE,
ALL RIGHT?
NOW HER SON HENRY'S
RUNNING THE JOINT.
HELLO AGAIN.
WHAT ARE THE THREE
KEY INGREDIENTS
TO--TO COSTA RICAN FOOD?
(Henry) VEGETABLES, MEAT,
AND CHICHARRóN.
AND CHICHARRóN!
I'M A BIG FAN OF PORK BELLY,
AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND CHEF OMAR CADENA...
CHICHARRóN
FOR THE CHIFRIJO.
IS SERVING IT UP
IN THIS CLASSIC.
CHIFRIJO'S READY TO GO.
TRADITIONAL
COSTA RICAN DISH.
AN APPETIZER WITH LOTS OF LAYERS
IN IT--THIS IS WONDERFUL.
SO WHAT ARE WE
MAKING, MAN?
THE CHICHARRóN
FOR THE CHIFRIJO.
WE START OFF
WITH THE RAW PORK BELLY.
MMM.
LOOK, ALL THIS RIGHT HERE...
DUDE, THIS IS
BODY BY CHICHARRóN.
YEAH, BODY BY CHICHARRóN.
THERE YOU GO.
I DIG IT.
SO CUT IT IN HALF.
WITH A SWASHBUCKLER'S
KNIFE.
CUT THIS IN STRIPS.
CUT 'EM INTO PIECES.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
DO WITH IT NOW?
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO OVER
TO THE STOVE AND START COOKING.
DO IT.
MAKE SURE THE PAN IS HOT.
A LITTLE OIL.
FROM HERE--YEAH, THERE WE GO.
THAT'S THE NEXT STEP.
THEN ADD THE CHICHARRóN.
COOK IT DOWN.
RENDER OUT THE FAT.
THE ONE MAIN INGREDIENT--
THE GARLIC,
LOTS OF GARLIC.
BIG CLOVES OF GARLIC.
OH, YEAH. SOME SALT.
YOU WANT TO GIVE IT A STIR.
I'LL HOLD IT DOWN
FOR YOU.
WOW. THAT SMELLS AWESOME.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA GO?
ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF.
COOK, BABY, COOK.
OKAY, PICO DE GALLO.
YEAH.
SOME DICED ONION, TOMATO,
CHOPPED CILANTRO,
MINCED JALAPEÑO--JUST RAW,
BEAUTIFULLY RAW.
AY.
SOME SALT, AND THEN WE'LL
JUICE SOME LEMONS.
OKAY, MIX IT UP?
YEAH.
LET THIS SET UP.
AND WE'RE ON
TO THE NEXT STEP.
THE PORK BELLY.
HERE WE GO.
LOAD IT UP IN HERE.
LET IT COOL FOR A DAY.
RIGHT.
WHERE ARE WE AT NOW?
COOLED OFF.
AND NOW WE CUT IT UP
INTO SMALL PIECES.
DUDE, YOU GOTTA
SERIOUSLY CHOP FASTER.
UH-HUH, LOSE A FINGER
LIKE THAT.
FINGER ON THAT.
AND HERE WE GO. WE'RE GONNA
FINALLY BUILD THE CHIFRIJO HERE.
YOU KNOW, SO AFTER
ALL THE BACK-AND-FORTH,
YOU KNOW,
THERE YOU GO.
MIYA!
CHICHARRóN IN THE FRYER,
TWO TO THREE MINUTES.
WE GOT OUR MORTAR-AND-PESTLE
DISH, A BIT OF BLACK BEAN SOUP.
A LITTLE RICE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA COVER IT
WITH THE BEANS.
OKAY.
CHICHARRóN
IS NICE AND CRISPY.
(whistles sharply)
CHICHARRóN ON TOP.
(chuckles)
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT OFF.
PICO DE GALLO.
YEAH, SO WE'RE GONNA DO--
QUARTER AN AVOCADO HERE.
AND THEN THIS--
IN COSTA RICAN FOOD--
LIZANO.
THE FAMOUS SALSA
OF COSTA RICA.
OH, MANO, I LOVE
THE LIZANO.
A LITTLE CHIPS FOR YOU
TO EAT IT WITH.
ARE YOU SUPPOSED
TO GO DOWN IN HERE
AND GET A BIG OL' BITE?
YEAH, AND IT
HAS TO BE MESSY.
MMM.
LOOK AT THOSE FLAVORS.
MMM! THE CHICHARRóN'S
ON POINT.
NICE FAT,
IT'S GOT NICE CRUNCH.
THE TOMATO, THE ONION...
CAN YOU FEEL IT?
I DON'T NEED TO GO ANYWHERE.
I'M IN COSTA RICA RIGHT NOW.
THERE WE GO.
I LIKE IT. BOOM.
GREAT JOB, MAN.
THE BOMB. OH!
(woman) CHIFRIJO.
IT'S MY STAPLE.
(Guy) THIS IS
YOUR GO-TO?
YES.
EVERYTHING HAS A REALLY STRONG
PRESENCE AND TASTE IN THE DISH.
IT'S REALLY YUMMY.
IT'S GOT A NICE,
LITTLE KICK TO IT.
IT'S EXCELLENT.
(woman) CARNE ASADA.
EVERYTHING IS JUST REALLY,
REALLY GOOD HERE.
PALMITO SALAD.
VEGETARIAN ITEMS,
A LOT OF MEAT,
FISH AND SEAFOOD,
AS WELL,
SO YOU CAN GET
ANYTHING THAT YOU WANT...
WHICH USUALLY MEANS
THEIR NUMBER ONE SANDWICH.
ONE PEPITO COMING UP.
WE GOTTA GO AHEAD
AND SALUTE THAT ONE.
IT'S A FAMILY RECIPE
WITH AN AUTHENTIC
COSTA RICAN BEAN PASTE.
PEPITO.
IF I'M GONNA HAVE A SANDWICH,
THIS IS WHAT I CRAVE.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
PEPITO--THE MOST
TYPICAL THING
OF CENTRAL AMERICAN
AND COSTA RICAN CUISINE
WITH THE BLACK BEANS.
SO THESE HAVE BEEN
PICKED THROUGH AND WASHED.
ADD IT TO THE POT.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE WATER.
AND WHEN DOES
THE GARLIC GO IN?
RIGHT NOW. THROW IT IN.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS GO?
AN HOUR
TO AN HOUR AND A HALF.
AS SOON AS IT GETS SOFT,
THEN WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
NOW?
SAUTé SOME ONION...
OKAY.
NICE, GOLDEN-COLORED BROWN.
BRING OUR BEANS OVER.
THEY'RE NICE
AND SOFT SO FAR?
PERFECT TENDER.
THERE YOU GO. NOW...
CARAMELIZED ONION.
AFTER THAT,
SALT, PEPPER, COMINO.
A LITTLE SUGAR?
A LITTLE SUGAR.
I LIKE IT.
AND NOW, 'CAUSE WE'RE MAKING
COSTA RICAN BLACK BEANS,
THE LIZANO SAUCE.
KINDA TASTES
LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN SOY SAUCE
AND ITALIAN DRESSING.
A NICE LITTLE MIX, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA PULL OUT THE WAND.
GO AHEAD, PAPO.
YOU DO IT.
OOH, YOU SHOULD SMELL IT.
AND SO WE GET THIS
ALL PURéED UP.
MMM. OH, I CAN'T WAIT
TO TRY THAT ON A SANDWICH.
NOW A LITTLE SCOOP OF OIL
RIGHT ON THE GRIDDLE.
THROW THE STEAK
ON THERE.
MEAN RIB EYE, HMM.
WE CAN'T FORGET
ABOUT THE ONIONS.
OKAY.
WE GOTTA SEASON IT A BIT--
GARLIC, SALT, PEPPER.
MMM.
ALL THOSE MEAT JUICES
COOKING THOSE ONIONS.
OH, YEAH, THEY'RE GETTING HAPPY
TOGETHER THERE, YOU KNOW?
OKAY.
I'M GONNA GET THE FRENCH BREAD.
IT COMES IN EVERY MORNING FRESH.
A LITTLE PURéED BLACK BEAN.
SO THE BEAN MAYONNAISE.
YEP, JUST A LITTLE SCHMEAR.
AND NOW MUENSTER CHEESE--
TO GET IT MELTING A LITTLE.
THIS IS READY TO GO ALREADY,
TAKES A HOT SECOND.
I LIKE WHERE YOU'RE
GOING WITH THIS.
I'M TELLING YOU.
THIS IS READY TO GO.
WHERE ARE YOU GONNA
PUT ALL THAT?
WE'RE GONNA STACK IT. WE'RE
GONNA LAYER THE STEAK, ONIONS.
ALL RIGHT.
THE LIZANO AGAIN,
'CAUSE IT'S GONNA MAKE
EVERYTHING COME TOGETHER.
BRING IT TO THE PRESS,
A LITTLE BUTTER,
GIVE IT A BRUSH.
LET IT GET NICE AND TOASTY.
TELL ME YOU DON'T WANT
TO JUST COME DOWN HERE
AND HANG OUT
WITH THIS GUY.
YOU READY TO EAT?
DO IT.
I'M GONNA TAKE IT OFF, BRING IT
OVER TO THE CUTTING BOARD.
AND THERE YOU HAVE IT--
OUR PEPITO SANDWICH.
LOOK HOW THICK THAT IS.
COME ON NOW.
MMM! THE BEANS--
PRIME TIME.
THE MEAT'S GREAT.
THE NICE BIG ONIONS. MMM.
THE LIZANO. IF YOU LOOK
INSIDE THESE VEINS RIGHT HERE,
LIZANO IS RUNNING UP AND DOWN
INSIDE OF THERE.
MMM. I CAN'T STOP
EATING IT.
THE BOMB.
YOU ROCKED IT.
HEY. FLATTERED.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ROCKED IT.
(woman) PEPITO.
IT'S SUPER DELICIOUS.
THE FLAVORS
JUST ALL MELD TOGETHER.
IT'S DIFFERENT
THAN ANY OTHER SANDWICH
THAT YOU CAN GET
IN THE CITY.
THE STEAK TICO.
I LOVE IRAZU.
STEAK CASADO.
FOR 20 YEARS, IT'S BEEN
CONSISTENT AND DELICIOUS.
(Omar) CHICHARRóN.
IF YOU HAVEN'T BEEN HERE,
YOU SHOULD ABSOLUTELY GET HERE.
IT'S AMAZING FOOD
AND AMAZING PEOPLE.
I THINK THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
WE'VE EVER HAD A CHANCE
TO COME AND TRY COSTA RICAN,
SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MY PLEASURE.
THANKS FOR COMING DOWN.
MOM, VERY NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
THE QUEEN.
UP NEXT...
I COULD JUST EAT THAT
AS IT IS.
WE'RE HEADED
TO SAN ANTONIO...
CHALUPA CABRA.
WHERE IT'S CHALUPAS...
ONE OF THE MOST UNIQUE DISHES
I THINK WE'VE HAD ON THE SHOW.
GONE WILD.
THAT'S A COSMIC WHIRLWIND
OF FLAVOR.
♪♪
I'M HERE IN NORTH CENTRAL
SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS,
ABOUT TEN MINUTES
FROM THE AIRPORT.
NOW WE'VE SHOT A LOT
OF GREAT JOINTS DOWN HERE,
AND PEOPLE ALWAYS SAY IT'S ALL
ABOUT THE TEX-MEX FOOD, RIGHT?
WELL, THE PLACE
I'M ABOUT TO VISIT--
PEOPLE MAY THINK IT'S TEX-MEX,
BUT I HEAR IT'S ALL ABOUT
LATIN AMERICAN STREET FOOD.
THIS IS BETO'S.
(man) ALL RIGHT,
I GOT A FISH TACO UP.
THE FOOD IS
CONSISTENTLY DELICIOUS.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THIS IS A UNIQUE RESTAURANT
FOR SAN ANTONIO.
(man) CEVICHE'S UP.
NOT ANY WAY
LIKE TEX-MEX.
I USUALLY JUST GO STRAIGHT
FOR THE EMPANADAS.
NOBODY DOES EMPANADAS
LIKE BETO'S DOES.
AND OWNERS BETO MIJANGOS...
I NEED ANOTHER
CHICKEN POBLANO.
AND HIS WIFE CHERYL...
THERE YOU GO.
HAVE BEEN DOING 'EM HERE
SINCE 1997.
WE RUN THROUGH ABOUT 1,500
TO 2,000 EMPANADAS A WEEK.
REALLY?
YEAH. WE'VE GOT
14 DIFFERENT VARIETIES.
FROM BEEF AND RED CHILI...
WONDERFUL.
TO CHICKEN MOLE...
VERY LIGHT.
IT'S VERY TASTY.
AND THIS TOP SELLER...
CHICKEN POBLANO EMPANADA.
IT STARTS
WITH THESE BAD BOYS.
IT'S NOT
A SUPEREXPENSIVE TOMATO
THAT'S DONE
IN ITS OWN WRAPPING.
THIS IS ACTUALLY A TOMATILLO.
OH, THE BOMB.
GIVE 'EM A LITTLE COOK.
WE WANT 'EM
KIND OF SOFT
FOR THE CHICKEN POBLANO
EMPANADA FILLING.
START WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR ONION, GET THAT SAUTéED.
GARLIC ON THIS GUY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR POBLANOS.
ROASTED POBLANOS.
ADD THOSE IN THERE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME CHICKEN STOCK.
MAKE THE CHICKEN STOCK
YOURSELF?
YEAH. OUR TOMATILLOS BACK IN.
YEAH, THANK YOU, BROTHER.
WE'LL GET YOU SPLASHED.
WE'LL ADD OUR PARSLEY,
SOME CILANTRO.
SALT. HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS COOK DOWN?
WE'RE GONNA STEW IT
A LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PURéE IT.
THIS ONE'S FROM
THE PAUL BUNYAN EDITION.
WHOA!
AS SOON AS YOU PULL THAT THING
UP, IT SPITS LIKE A VIPER.
SO THAT'S ALL KNOCKED OUT.
LET IT SIT THERE
AND SIMMER
A LITTLE LONGER?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
TOMATILLO SALSA IS DONE,
AND THIS IS TO COMBINE
ALL THE FILLING THAT'S GOING FOR
THE CHICKEN POBLANO EMPANADA.
EXACTLY.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF ONION.
WE'LL DO A LITTLE GARLIC.
MMM.
ADD OUR ROASTED
POBLANO PEPPERS.
HENCE THE NAME--
CHICKEN POBLANO.
HENCE THE NAME.
ADD OUR TOMATILLO SAUCE
THAT WE HAD MADE EARLIER.
I COULD JUST EAT THAT
AS IT IS.
SOME LIME JUICE,
SOME HEAVY CREAM IN HERE.
MIX THAT IN THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
BLACK PEPPER...
GET THAT ALL GOING
REAL GOOD.
I DON'T CARE WHAT
YOU PUT THAT ON.
ROASTED CHICKEN BREAST,
BONELESS SKINLESS.
THIS IS WHERE THE OOEY-GOOEY
COMES--OUR CHEESE.
I'M GONNA ADD A LOT OF THIS
LITTLE CHEESE IN HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA MIX IT UP,
LET IT COOL, AND THEN
FILL THE EMPANADAS.
WE GOT OUR LITTLE PASTRY.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S STUFF 'EM.
WE'LL JUST PUT SOME
IN THE CENTER,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
JUST FOLD THAT PUPPY OVER.
AND THEN YOU WANT ME
TO FORK IT?
PLEASE DO, MAN.
THIS IS HOW
THEY ALL GO.
YEP, AND THEY'RE READY,
AND GET 'EM IN THE OVEN NOW.
A LITTLE EGG WASH ON THAT.
COOL.
WE HAVE A LITTLE QUICK OVEN
THAT WE CAN GET 'EM POPPED UP
IN ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
WE'VE GOT THIS READY TO GO, MAN.
MMM.
YOU CAN REALLY TASTE
THE FLAVORS, SOME
OF THE ACID OF THE TOMATILLO.
YOU GET A LITTLE OF THE POBLANO.
YOU GET THE ROASTED PEPPER
IN THERE.
YOU GET THE CHICKEN.
NICE, FLAKY CRUST.
I THINK THAT IS A REAL
CONTEMPORARY ATTITUDE
TOWARDS WHAT I THINK
PEOPLE THINK LATIN FOOD IS,
AND YOU TAKE TIME
TO COOK IT THE RIGHT WAY. MMM.
WELL DONE, MAN.
(man) WE GOT
THE CHICKEN POBLANO EMPANADA.
IT'S SCRUMPTIOUS.
(woman) IT'S VERY SAVORY.
MMM.
THEY MAKE IT TO ORDER,
SO IT'S FRESH.
HERE'S YOUR
PERUVIAN CEVICHE.
YOU CAN GET THINGS HERE
THAT YOU CAN'T GET ANYWHERE ELSE
IN SAN ANTONIO.
WE COOK AND TASTE
AND TRY.
WE LOVE TO BE CREATIVE.
YOU THINK?
(Beto)
CHALUPA CABRA.
THAT'S BETO'S TAKE
ON A MEXICAN CHALUPA.
IT'S AMAZING. I DON'T KNOW HALF
THE THINGS THAT ARE IN IT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING,
BROTHER?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
CHALUPA CABRA.
(speaking Spanish)
YOU EVER HEARD
OF A CHUPACABRA?
YES, I DROVE ONE
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
(imitating car engine)
YEAH. GEAR SHIFTED.
SO GET US STARTED.
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH CABRITO.
CABRITO IS THE "SMALL GOAT."
YEAH. DO THE MARINADE FIRST
WITH A LITTLE WHITE VINEGAR,
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL, A LITTLE
SALT, AND A LITTLE PEPPER.
VERY SIMPLE VINAIGRETTE.
WHISK THAT UP,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA TOSS
OUR LITTLE BABIES IN HERE.
A LITTLE T-BONE
RIGHT THERE.
SO WE'LL MARINATE THIS
FOR A COUPLE HOURS,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA START
COOKING THIS PUPPY UP.
OKAY, IT'S NOT PUPPY.
IT'S GOAT.
GOAT, YEAH.
OLIVE OIL. NOW WE'RE GONNA
BROWN THE CABRITO.
SMELL THAT VINEGAR COOKING OFF
RIGHT NOW. OKAY.
WE'VE GOT OUR CABRITO
NOW BROWNED.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD IT
TO A STOCK POT--
OLIVE OIL, ONIONS IN,
OUR CARROTS, POTATO.
OF COURSE, WE'VE GOTTA HAVE
GARLIC IN EVERYTHING, I THINK,
RIGHT?
I AGREE.
NOW WE'RE READY FOR OUR CABRITO,
CHICKEN STOCK,
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
SALT, PEPPER.
AND A BIG TOUCH OF THE CURRY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR PARSLEY,
THYME, AND BAY LEAF.
NOW WE WRAP IT.
WE'VE GOT OUR SPICE BAG.
SO YOU COVER THIS,
LET IT SIT HERE AND STEW
TWO TO THREE HOURS?
EXACTLY.
SO THE GOAT'S ROASTING.
YEAH.
NOW WHAT ARE WE INTO?
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GUAVA
AND CREAM CHEESE ROLLS.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA.
THE GUAVA
AND CREAM CHEESE ROLL.
THIS IS JUST STRAIGHT
OLD PASTRY DOUGH.
YEP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA LAYER
OUR CREAM CHEESE IN HERE,
ADD OUR GUAVA PASTE.
SO WE'LL ROLL THIS THING UP NOW.
AND WE'RE GONNA TUCK
THE LITTLE ENDS IN
SO ALL THE GOODIES
DON'T COME OUT.
SO YOU THROW IT
IN THE FRIDGE,
LET IT COOL OUT
FOR AN HOUR, BRING IT OUT.
YEAH, IT'S FIRM, FIRM PLACE.
CUT IT INTO SLICES,
OF COURSE.
WE'RE GONNA
CUT IT INTO SLICES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
BAKE IT OFF.
COOL.
ALL RIGHT, MAN, SO THESE ARE
THE GUAVA ROLLS THAT WE MADE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR CABRITO MEAT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA LADLE
SOME OF THE SAUCE,
AND THAT'S GOT THAT
CURRY IN THERE.
NOT EXACTLY WHAT I WAS EXPECTING
TO FIND IN SAN ANTONIO.
AND WE'LL PUT OUR CILANTRO SLAW
AND SOME COCONUT
TO GIVE IT A LITTLE CRUNCH
THERE, AS WELL.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU KNOW,
ALL THE BASIC STUFF.
MMM.
DUDE, THAT'S A SURPRISER
RIGHT THERE.
APPRECIATE IT.
THAT IS A "WAKE UP AND KICK YOU
IN THE LUNCHBOX" ON THAT ONE.
THE SWEETNESS OF THE GUAVA
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SOUR
OF THE CREAM CHEESE--
THEN YOU BRING IN THIS
REALLY DEEP ROASTED FLAVOR
OF THE CABRITO. MMM.
AND THIS CURRY SAUCE,
WHICH HAS ITS OWN
STRONG REPRESENTATION.
THAT'S A COSMIC WHIRLWIND
OF FLAVOR. KILLER.
YEAH.
HERE'S YOUR
CHALUPA CABRA.
AND IT WAS SWEET,
KIND OF A SOUR TASTE
ALL AT THE SAME TIME.
ONE OF THE MOST UNIQUE DISHES
I THINK WE'VE HAD ON THE SHOW.
I LOVE EVERYTHING
THEY HAVE HERE.
(speaking indistinctly)
COMBO 1.
THIS IS FAR BEYOND TEX-MEX.
GOTTA COME CHECK IT OUT.
UP NEXT...
(woman) THE TORTILLAS
ARE HOT.
I'M HEADED
TO QUEENS, NEW YORK...
SMELLS GREAT.
WHERE IT'S TIME
TO MAKE THE MASA...
CHECK THAT OUT.
AT THE TORTILLA CASA.
MMM. PRIME TIME.
♪♪
RESTAURANTS SERVE SO MANY
PURPOSES IN A COMMUNITY--
I MEAN, OF COURSE,
GREAT FOOD AND SERVICE.
AND SOMETIMES THEY FULFILL
A CULTURAL NEED,
LIKE HERE IN CORONA, QUEENS,
IN NEW YORK CITY,
WHERE THESE FOLKS ARE MAKING
TRADITIONAL MEXICAN FOOD
AND ALSO OVER 6,000 POUNDS
OF MASA,
USED TO MAKE TORTILLAS
AND TAMALES,
SOMETHING YOU COULDN'T FIND
AROUND HERE
UNTIL THIS PLACE OPENED UP.
THIS IS TORTILLERIA NIXTAMAL.
TAMALE MOLE.
I CAN'T HAVE A TAMALE
ANYWHERE ELSE NOW.
TRY THIS. MMM.
YEAH, THANKS. THANKS FOR
LEAVING ME A LITTLE BIT.
GOT THE CILANTRO AND ONIONS
FOR THE PORK TACOS.
DEFINITELY THE BEST
MEXICAN FOOD
I'VE HAD IN NEW YORK.
(man) ENCHILADAS.
VERY AUTHENTIC.
STEAK TOSTADA.
I WANTED TO DO
SOMETHING TRADITIONAL
FOR THE LOCAL
MEXICAN COMMUNITY.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
EVEN THOUGH FIREFIGHTER
FERNANDO RUIZ
AND HIS GIRLFRIEND
SHAUNA PAGE...
MACIZA'S UP.
HAD NEVER OWNED
A RESTAURANT.
(Fernando) I ALWAYS WONDERED
WHY THE CUISINE IN MEXICO
WAS SO MUCH BETTER
THAN IN NEW YORK.
ONE OF THE KEY INGREDIENTS
WAS THE TORTILLAS.
SO THEY BOUGHT THE GEAR...
(Guy) ALL THE MACHINERY
IS FROM MEXICO.
CORRECT.
WHOO, HOT.
AND LEARNED HOW TO MAKE 'EM
OLD-SCHOOL.
TORTILLAS FROM NIXTAMAL.
IT'S BASICALLY
CORN THAT'S DRY...
RIGHT.
THEN COOKED WITH LIME.
THIS IS THE WAY THE AZTEC
INTENDED IT.
LET'S MAKE IT.
DRY CORN.
LOOK AT THE PIPES
ON HER.
5 50-POUND BAGS.
(corn rustling)
NOW LIME.
THE LIME ON THERE IS GONNA
TAKE THE SKINS OFF.
YES. ADD WATER TO IT.
WOW.
CAPTAIN, WE ALMOST GOT
THE FIRE OUT!
SHUTTIN' HER DOWN. CALL ME WHEN
YOU WANT ME TO DO THIS AGAIN.
OKAY.
NOW STIR IT AROUND.
COOK IT AT 200 DEGREES.
FOR ABOUT THREE AND A HALF
TO FOUR HOURS
AND SIT OVERNIGHT.
THEN FERNANDO
CAN FINISH THE JOB.
THIS IS A BAZOOKA WASHER.
IS THAT WHAT
THEY CALL IT?
IN MEXICO.
NICE.
TURN THE WATER ON.
HIT THAT SWITCH.
IT'S GONNA BRING IT UP.
IT'S GONNA INFUSE CLEAN WATER.
IT'S GONNA RINSE
THE CORN OFF.
IT'S IN A TROUGH,
SPINNING LIKE THIS...
CORRECT.
WASHING AS IT GOES.
WE GOTTA GET THE LIME,
THE SKINS OFF.
AND THEN IT'S DEPOSITED
IN THE STONE GRINDER.
AND THAT MAKES THE MASA.
CORRECT. AND WE'RE
READY TO GO.
ALL THE FRICTION THAT'S GOING ON
BETWEEN THE TWO STONE WHEELS--
CHECK THAT OUT.
HOT.
NOW THAT THE MASA'S GROUND,
I HAVE TO PUT IT IN THE MIXER
TO MAKE A DOUGH BALL
AND TRANSFER IT
INTO THE MACHINE.
THIS THING IS SMOKIN'-HOT.
NOW WE'LL MAKE THE TORTILLAS.
SO WE'VE GOT
THE RIGHT CONSISTENCY.
THIS CONVEYOR'S
ALREADY HOT HERE...
CORRECT.
SO AS SOON AS IT COMES DOWN,
THIS IS LIKE PUTTING IT...
ON A SKILLET.
SO IT'LL GO DOWN, DROP,
BACK DOWN, DROP,
BACK DOWN, DROP.
BOTH SIDES THREE TIMES.
IT'S LIKE "LAVERNE & SHIRLEY"
MEETS LUCILLE BALL.
HERE THEY COME. LOOK AT THAT.
IT IS STEAMING HOT.
MMM. GREAT FLAVOR.
AND THIS IS HOW IT GOES
ALL DAY?
EVERY DAY.
UP TO 10,000 OF 'EM.
(Shauna)
THE TORTILLAS ARE HOT.
THEY ARE THE BEST
IN THE FIVE BOROUGHS.
HOT AND SCRUMPTIOUS
AND DELICIOUS.
YEAH.
WE'D OPEN OUR OWN TAQUERIA,
AND WE'D GET OUR CORN TORTILLAS
FROM NIXTAMAL.
DELIVERED EVERY MORNING.
OR YOU COULD
JUST COME HERE...
TORTILLAS ARE READY.
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING 'EM
STUFFED...
ENCHILADAS DE MOLE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FRIED...
TOSTADA DE STEAK.
AND LOADED
WITH THE CLASSICS.
(man) TACO AL PASTOR--
VERY TRADITIONAL
SLOW-ROASTED PORK ON A SPIT
WITH HALF OF A PINEAPPLE
STUCK ON THE TOP.
REALLY, REALLY TENDER.
(Guy)
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
THE ADOBO SAUCE
FOR THE AL PASTOR.
(chuckles) OH.
FIRST...
ANNATTO PASTE--
GREAT COLOR.
THEN HAM BASE,
MEXICAN SEASONED SALT.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE
SOME CHICKEN BASE.
YES.
OREGANO, GARLIC, ONION,
SALT, WORCESTERSHIRE.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
AND THEN GUAJILLO PEPPERS...
THAT HAVE BEEN STEEPED
IN HOT WATER.
FRESH PINEAPPLE JUICE.
GREAT ENZYMES IN THE PINEAPPLE
FOR MARINATING.
VINEGAR.
BLEND IT UP.
AY!
START MARINATING.
LITTLE SPLASHY SPLASH.
ADD SOME
OF THE PORK BUTT.
THINLY SLICED.
SAUCE. NOW A LAYER
OF PINEAPPLE.
ONIONS IN EACH
LAYER, TOO?
YES.
THIS IS A MEXICAN LASAGNA.
YEAH, A MEAT LASAGNA.
IT'S GONNA
MARINATE OVERNIGHT.
AND WE'LL STACK IT
ON THE VERTICAL ROTISSERIE.
YES.
CATCH ALL THE JUICES.
SO WE'VE GOT OUR MARINATED PORK.
WE'RE GONNA STICK
AN ONION.
CREATE THE DOMING.
THE FIRST LAYER OF MEAT
AND PINEAPPLE
AND OUR ONIONS THAT HAVE BEEN
MARINATING IN SALT.
AND THEN YOU PUT
MORE MEAT.
SO IT'S JUST MEAT,
PINEAPPLE, ONIONS,
MEAT, PINEAPPLE, ONIONS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THEN A PINEAPPLE
ON TOP.
NOW LET'S LOAD IT
INTO THE ROTISSERIE.
AND HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
TO COOK ON THERE?
ABOUT 15
TO 20 MINUTES.
THIS IS AWESOME.
SO IT'S READY
TO BE CARVED.
NICE AND SEARED,
YOU CAN SEE.
SMELLS GREAT.
SUPERSHARP KNIFE HELPS SO YOU
DON'T TEAR THE MEAT OFF OF IT.
YEAH. AND I'M GOING
TO COOK IT SOME MORE.
RIGHT THERE.
SOME MORE, HUH? MMM.
FRESH TORTILLAS.
DO YOU WARM THOSE UP?
THE AL PASTOR IS READY.
THEN WE JUST NEED TO TOP IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE PINEAPPLE,
AND IT'S READY FOR YOU.
OKAY. YOU GOTTA REALLY HAVE IT
AS AN ENSEMBLE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT?
YES, I DO.
SOME WHITE ONION, A SQUEEZE
OF SOME LIME, A LITTLE CILANTRO.
DRUMROLL.
OH, ALL RIGHT.
PRIME TIME. YOU DO
ALL THE PIECES RIGHT--
THE PORK,
THE VERTICAL ROTISSERIE,
FRESH PINEAPPLE,
NICE FRESH TORTILLA. MMM.
NICE JOB.
PASTOR'S READY.
THE PORK
AND THE PINEAPPLE--
SMOKY AND SWEET.
AND THE FRESH TORTILLA--
MMM--MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
(man) AND A MILANESA.
(man) YOU CAN TASTE
THE FRESHNESS,
AND IT JUST FEELS LIKE
THEY JUST MADE IT.
THEY DID, ACTUALLY.
LIKE ONE OF MY
ALL-TIME FAVORITES...
(man) POZOLE.
I LOVE POZOLE.
AND WE'RE MAKING IT NEXT.
MMM.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S FRESH.
OH. I THOUGHT YOU GUYS
WENT TO COMMERCIAL.
(Shauna laughs)
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
AFTER THIS.
♪♪
STEAK TOSTADAS UP.
AT TORTILLERIA NIXTAMAL
IN CORONA, QUEENS, NEW YORK,
OWNERS SHAUNA PAGE...
MAKING THE MACIZA.
AND FERNANDO RUIZ...
ENJOY, GENTLEMEN.
ARE TAKING THEIR MEXICAN FOOD
BACK TO ITS ROOTS
WITH ONE INGREDIENT--
YOU GOT IT--CORN.
THEY'RE GRINDING IT...
I LOVE THE TAMALES.
ROLLING IT...
I CAN EAT THE TORTILLA
BY ITSELF.
AND EVEN SERVING IT UP WHOLE
WITH THIS FAN FAVORITE.
POZOLE.
THE LITTLE
CORN NUGGETS
ARE WHAT KEEPS ME
COMING BACK.
THAT'D BE NIXTAMAL--
CORN THAT'S COOKED
AND RINSED.
SO ONCE THE SKIN COMES OFF,
IT'S POZOLE TIME.
POZOLE, YES.
(inhales sharply)
I LOVE POZOLE.
MY JOWLS ARE JUST FLOODING.
IT'S LIKE NIAGARA.
LET'S GET IT GOING.
ALL RIGHT.
SEAR OUR MEAT IN OLIVE OIL.
WHAT PART OF LE PIG
IS THAT?
SHOULDER.
SKIN ON, THE WHOLE THING.
THEN I ADD
SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
SEAR BOTH SIDES. OKAY.
RIGHT. ADD WATER.
AND YOU'RE GONNA LET THIS COOK
LOW AND SLOW FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT AN HOUR UNTIL THE MEAT
IS SOFT, AND CUBE IT.
OKAY.
AND AFTER THAT?
MAKE THE SEASONING
FOR THE BROTH.
GARLIC-- AJO--
AND THE ONION.
CEBOLLA.
DO YOU SPEAK SPANISH?
Sí, UN POCO.
YEAH, I KNOW
ABOUT "PINOCCHIO," TOO,
BUT I THINK IT'S--
I THINK IT'S AN ITALIAN BOOK.
OREGANO, SALT, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME BROTH
FROM THE ALREADY
COOKED PORK. GRACIAS.
DE NADA.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
MIX IT UP.
DROP THE HAMMER!
THAT'S GOOD.
OKAY.
NOW LET'S PUT THE NIXTAMAL
INTO THE HOT WATER. IT'LL BOIL.
ABOUT AN HOUR?
YES, UNTIL THE CORN
PLUMPS UP.
COOLS DOWN.
ADD IT TO OUR BROTH
WITH THE WATER.
'CAUSE THAT'S FLAVOR.
GO. GO.
(whispering) YEAH.
ADD OUR SEASONING
THAT WE BLENDED UP.
ADD OUR MEAT
THAT WE CUBED.
(normal voice)
AND THE BONES?
AND THE BONES. THE BONE'S
THE MOST IMPORTANT PART.
TONS OF FLAVOR THERE.
SO EVERYTHING--
THAT ENTIRE PORK SHOULDER.
LET THIS ALL COME BACK UP
TO A SIMMER.
45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR.
DIDN'T YOU MAKE ANY
FOR YOURSELF?
I MADE SOME FOR YOU.
THE POZOLE'S READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE GREAT THING
ABOUT POZOLE IS YOU CAN
KINDA SEASON IT
THE WAY YOU WANT.
NOW HOW DO YOU MAKE YOURS?
A LOT OF LIME, ONIONS,
LETTUCE, OREGANO.
THE RADISH.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
I THINK THAT'S THE FIRST TIME
I'VE SEEN THAT TECHNIQUE.
(laughs) WELL...
IT WORKED, THOUGH.
I GOTTA HAVE A LITTLE HOT SAUCE,
A LITTLE COLOR TO MINE.
OLé, POZOLE.
MMM. THIS IS SUCH
COMFORT FOOD 101.
THAT'S GREAT.
SUCH GREAT TEXTURE.
A LITTLE TORTILLA OVER HERE.
MAKING THE BROTH
OUT OF COOKING THE PORK,
RE-ADDING EVERYTHING
INTO IT...
MM-HMM.
MMM. GREAT JOB.
POZOLE FOR YOU.
IT'S VERY HEARTY.
SO SOOTHING.
(woman) ENCHILADA VERDE.
(man)
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
IT'S A GEM
FOR ALL US LOCALS.
AND THIS IS HOW
IT'S DONE, MAN.
YOU'VE GOT ALL THE TOYS,
ALL THE BELLS,
ALL THE WHISTLES, AND FRESH
TORTILLAS LIKE WE GET IN MEXICO.
GOOD JOB, GUYS.
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(man)
RUN FOR YOUR LIVES!
(laughing)