HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
YAH, YOU CAN HEAR IT NOW.
IT'S LIKE A MOTORBOAT ENGINE.
(imitating lightsaber)
IT'S TRIPLE "D"
GOIN' TRIPLE "P"--
PORK...
(normal voice)
ROCKIN' IT.
PANCAKES...
THE GLAZE IS DYNAMITE.
AND PIZZA.
LOOK AT THAT!
IN CHICAGO, TWO BUDDIES...
TYPICAL
CHICAGO-STYLE FOOD?
NO.
TRADIN' PORK BELLY.
IS ALL OF THAT, UM...
FOR A WHOLE PO'BOY.
IT'S LIKE
A CANOE OF PORK.
MMM.
LIKE 'EM.
IN VIRGINIA BEACH,
A BREAKFAST PLACE...
THIS MEANS YOU'RE SERIOUS.
SHOWIN' OFF...
WHOA!
THE SUNNIER SIDE
OF PANCAKES.
COLD PIZZA,
THE SPORTS PAGE--
AND SOME CITRUS PANCAKES.
WAY TO GO.
THANK YOU.
AND IN DOWNTOWN DETROIT...
DO YOU THINK THIS IS SOME
OF THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN?
IT'S DEFINITELY
THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
A LARGE SUPINO
COMIN' UP.
A PIZZERIA TAKIN' TOPPINGS...
THE ROASTED GARLIC,
CHERRY PEPPERS--
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
BRINED, SMOKED
TURKEY LEGS.
YES, SIR.
SEE IT EVERY DAY.
YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN ONE OF MY FAVORITE FOOD TOWNS
IN THE COUNTRY--CHICAGO.
NOW I'M ABOUT A MILE NORTH
OF DOWNTOWN,
IN WHAT WAS ONCE
A PRETTY ROUGH NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT'S A PERFECT
TRIPLE "D" STORY, THOUGH.
TWO BEST FRIENDS
SINCE THIRD GRADE
PUT IT ALL ON THE LINE
TO OPEN UP--GET THIS--
A GOURMET FAST FOOD JOINT.
THIS IS BIG & LITTLE'S.
DONNY, ONE SHRIMP AND FRY.
THANK YOU.
GARY, I'M DROPPIN'
A PORK BELLY.
TYPICAL
CHICAGO-STYLE FOOD?
NO, NOT REALLY.
NO.
THIS DUDE AIN'T KIDDIN'.
ONE SOFT-SHELL CRAB
PO'BOY.
(man) I'VE TRIED FOIE GRAS
FOR THE FIRST TIME HERE.
I'VE TRIED SOFT-SHELL CRAB
FOR THE FIRST TIME HERE,
SMELT FOR THE FIRST TIME HERE.
(man) I COME HERE
'CAUSE IT'S INEXPENSIVE
AND EVERYTHING'S FRESH.
IT'S LIKE, UH, QUICK
GOURMET FOOD.
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU?
THAT WAS THE WHOLE IDEA
FOR BIG GARY STRAUSS
AND LITTLE TONY D'ALESSANDRO,
FRIENDS WHO CAME CLOSE
TO OPENIN' A HIP-HOP CLUB
BEFORE GOIN' GRUNGE GOURMET.
WE WERE TALKIN' LIKE, "OH, WE
SHOULD CALL IT BIGGIE SMALLS,"
AND THEN "BIG & LITTLE'S,"
AND THEN IT POPPED UP.
I DIG IT.
THE PLACE OPENED IN '09
ON A BLOCK THAT WAS MISSIN'
A COUPLE OF BUILDINGS,
BUT THAT DIDN'T STOP FOLKS
FROM GETTIN' IN LINE.
IT'S LIKE A PARTY
IN YOUR MOUTH,
BUT NOT LIKE--WELL, THAT
WOULD BE AN UNDERSTATEMENT.
IT'S LIKE A--
SO IT'S LIKE A RAGER.
IT'S LIKE A 6-KEG RAGER.
AND THE NUMBER ONE RAGER...
(Tony) PORK BELLY PO'BOY.
I GOT SOMETHIN' CALLED
A PORK BELLY PO'BOY.
PORK BELLY PO'BOY.
RIGHT.
ALL THOSE THINGS
WORK FOR ME.
ALL RIGHT, FIRST I'M GONNA
CUT IT INTO LONG STRIPS.
OH, TWEAKY-TWEAKY
WITH THAT, BRO.
SO YOU'RE GONNA
CUBE THIS IN 1x1s?
GIVE OR TAKE,
PLUS OR MINUS.
NOW WHAT'S THE PROCESS
FROM HERE?
KOSHER SALT,
SEASON THE WATER
SO IT, LIKE, SWIMS
WITH ALL THIS PORK.
BRING IT TO A ROLLING BOIL.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL IT FOR
TWO AND A HALF, THREE HOURS,
UNTIL, UH, THE FAT
AND--AND THE ACTUAL MEAT
ON THE FAT
IS NICE AND TENDER,
LIKE BUTTER.
YOU JUST DID, LIKE,
A DE NIRO OR SOMETHING.
(Italian accent) SO YOU KNOW
WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT, MAN?
(as Robert De Niro) WHEN
THE FAT COME TO THE TOP.
(normal voice) GONNA MAKE
A MAPLE GLAZE HERE,
ALL RIGHT, GOES RIGHT ON TOP
OF THE PORK BELLY.
I'M GONNA TAKE
SOME EGG YOLKS...
(normal voice) OKAY.
LEMON JUICE,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
A COUPLE DROPS,
START IT UP.
OH, SO WE ARE MAKING
MAPLE MAYONNAISE.
PRETTY MUCH.
AND THEN MIX THE MAYO
AND MAPLE SYRUP TOGETHER.
THIS IS ACTUALLY WEIRD.
WE'RE GONNA FRY
SOME PORK BELLY CUBES.
WORD.
YOU READY?
(whistles)
IS ALL OF THAT, UM...
YEAH, FOR A WHOLE PO'BOY.
ALL OF IT?
YEAH. LET'S SEE.
YEAH.
SALT.
I CAN HEAR IT CRACKLIN'.
WE GOT THAT READY.
SO THE PORK COMES OUT...
MMM.
SO I GIVE IT CHICHARRONES
MEETS PULLED PORK.
YOU GOT IT, MAN.
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
YOU THINK I GOT IT?
I'M AWESOME WITH THAT.
OKAY, GO.
A LITTLE LOUISIANA HOT SAUCE,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THIS MAPLE GLAZE...
WHICH IS ACTUALLY...
(whispering)
MAPLE MAYONNAISE.
SO A LITTLE BIT
OF SHREDDED LETTUCE,
SOME NICE DILL PICKLES.
NOW I PUT THIS
IN OUR BASKET.
(normal voice)
SO IT'LL HOLD
THE MOUNTAINOUS MEAT
THAT IS COMING.
(whistles)
THEN WE FINISH IT--
OF COURSE WE DO.
MAPLE GLAZE.
TA-DA.
IT'S LIKE
A CANOE OF PORK.
MMM.
(mumbling)
MMM. LIKE 'EM.
ALL THE PIECES
PLAY REALLY WELL TOGETHER.
THE HOT SAUCE
WITH THE MAPLE MAYO
WITH THE SALTY PORK--
ROCKIN' IT.
LOAD THE FAMILY TRUCKSTER.
BRING EVERYBODY DOWN.
YOU GUYS
COULD SHARE ALL THIS
AND EAT IT LIKE
A THANKSGIVING TURKEY PIG.
EXCITING SANDWICH.
IT'S THE FINER SWINER.
(chuckling)
COME ON,
ONE SMELT PO'BOY.
THEY'RE HAVIN' FUN NOW,
BUT THESE GUYS ROLLED
SOME PRETTY BIG DICE
TO GET IT GOIN'.
I SOLD MY APARTMENT
AND MY CAR.
YOU SOLD YOUR APARTMENT,
SO YOU GUYS REALLY DID
PUT IT ALL ON THE LINE
TO MAKE IT HAPPEN.
YEAH.
THE GAMBLE DEFINITELY PAID OFF.
WHEN YOU THINK
OF DOWNTOWN CHICAGO,
YOU'RE THINKING BIG PRICES,
SMALL PORTIONS.
EXACTLY OPPOSITE HERE.
SO, I MEAN,
IT IS GOURMET FAST FOOD.
COULD YOU CALL IT
SOMETHING ELSE?
I DON'T THINK SO.
NO, IT'S JUST THE BOMB.
I'VE NEVER HAD
SUCH GOOD SEAFOOD,
SO QUICK, IN THE CITY.
(woman) BEST FISH AND CHIPS.
I ALWAYS HAVE IT
WHEN I COME HERE.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
YEP.
WE'RE MAKIN' BEER BATTER
FISH AND CHIPS.
OKAY.
FLOUR, SALT.
WANT ME TO START
CRACKIN' THESE?
START CRACKIN' EM, MAN.
GOT IT.
READY?
YEAH, LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE MASH IT.
(man) OHH, OHH!
OH, MY GOD, I'M SORRY.
HE MAKES A MESS,
BUT YOU GOTTA LOVE A CHEF
MAKIN' HIS OWN TARTAR SAUCE.
SO WE'LL LET THIS
SET UP FOR--
IT'S NOT REALLY
EVEN POSSIBLE, IS IT?
OKAY, BATTER'S
SUPER MEGA CHILL,
AND THIS IS LE COD.
MY CUSTOMERS CALL IT
THE WHALE.
OKAY.
DREDGE IT WITH SOME FLOUR.
NO SALT?
NO SALT.
SALT'S IN THE BATTER.
OKAY.
BRING IT TO THE FRYER.
YOU GOTTA STAND BACK.
ALL RIGHT, EVIDENTLY.
SO YOU WAFT THAT
BACK AND FORTH
UNTIL YOU START TO BUILD
SOME OF THE CRUST,
AND IT FLOATS.
THESE DUDES ARE EVEN
FRESH-CUTTIN'
AND DOUBLE-FRYIN' THE CHIPS.
HERE WE GO.
WHOA.
IT'S A BEAUTY, ISN'T IT?
LOOK AT THAT.
WOW.
WHOA, LOOK AT THAT.
NICE CRUST.
YEAH.
MMM.
IT'S TENDER,
NOT DRIED OUT,
VERY LIGHT,
AND THE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THAT--
JUST LISTEN TO THIS.
(crackling)
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT
WITH A STICK.
BIG FILET OF COD,
NICELY BATTERED.
I UNDERSTAND THE "BIG"
IN BIG & LITTLE--
BIG,
PLACE IS LITTLE.
NOW I GOT IT.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
YOU GOT IT, MAN.
YOU KILLED IT ON
THE FISH AND CHIPS.
YOU'VE ROCKED IT
ON THE PORK SANDWICH.
WHAT IS NEXT?
FOIE GRAS AND FRIES.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE HANGIN' OUT IN CHICAGO
WITH TONY AT BIG & LITTLE'S.
YOU GOTTA COME BACK FOR THIS.
TRIPLE "D" IS ROLLIN'
AT BIG & LITTLE'S
ON CHICAGO'S NORTH SIDE.
HERE, BIG IS GARY STRAUSS
AND LITTLE
IS CHEF TONY D'ALESSANDRO...
PORK BELLY IS READY.
LIFELONG FRIENDS WHO TURNED
THIS 12-SEAT JOINT...
ONE MAHI TACO.
INTO A FULL-BLOWN
TRIPLE "D" RAGER.
FOIE GRAS AND FRIES.
WHAT ARE WE UP TO, BOSS?
WE'RE GONNA DO, UH,
FOIE GRAS AND FRIES.
ALL RIGHT,
SEE IT EVERY DAY.
SWEET, MAN.
TAKE MY KNIFE,
STICK IT IN THE GRILL.
SO IT'LL CUT THROUGH
THE FOIE GRAS LIKE "BUTTAH."
OKAY, SO YOU SCORE THAT
A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN WE'LL SALT,
CRACKED PEPPER.
TAKE THE FOIE GRAS--
MUFF IT IN THE PAN.
90% FAT
WE'RE LOOKIN' AT HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
GET ANOTHER PAN,
PUT IT ON TOP.
FOR THE FRIES,
THE POTATOES ARE FRESH-CUT
INTO SHOESTRINGS
AND DOUBLE-FRIED
FOR EXTRA CRUNCH.
SEE ALL THAT NATURAL FAT
WE'RE DEALIN' WITH?
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S PURE DUCK FAT.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
READY TO ROCK?
I'M READY TO ROCK, MAN.
(whistles)
THAT IS AN ORDER
OF FOIE GRAS.
NOW THE BEST PART IS HERE.
WE TAKE THIS DUCK FAT--
(whistling)
MIGHT BE THE ONLY TIME YOU'LL
SEE ANYBODY ON FOOD NETWORK
EATING FOIE GRAS WITH
A PLASTIC FORK AND KNIFE.
♪♪
WHAT YOU HAVE HERE
IS PERFECTLY COOKED,
MEDIUM-RARE,
NICE...
JUICY LADLING
OF THE DUCK FAT
ONTO THE SUPER-CRISPY
SHOESTRING FRIES.
THE REAL KEY TO THIS
IS IT'S ONLY...
12 BUCKS.
YEAH, SON.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
(chuckling)
NEVER IN A MILLION YEARS WOULD
I HAVE DRIVEN BY THIS PLACE
AND SAID, "YOU KNOW WHAT?
I BET YOU THEY HAVE
GOOD FOIE GRAS IN THERE."
GREG, FOIE GRAS AND FRIES.
I'D EATEN FOIE GRAS
AND EATEN FRENCH FRIES,
BUT NEVER TOGETHER.
THEY'RE JUST, LIKE, DECADENT.
IT'S AMAZING.
IF YOU GO INTO
A FINE DINING RESTAURANT,
YOU'RE LOOKING AT,
LIKE, $25 FOR FOIE GRAS.
EASILY.
EASY.
AND NO FRIES.
NO FRIES, TO BOOT.
SHOVEL DOWN THERE, HOMEY.
ONLY ON TRIPLE "D" WILL YOU SEE
PEOPLE EATIN' FOIE GRAS
WITH THEIR FINGERS.
(Guy) THIS IS
THE ALL-AMERICAN STORY--
TWO BEST FRIENDS COME TOGETHER,
PUT IT ALL ON THE LINE,
SELL THE CAR,
SELL THE APARTMENT--
THIS IS WHAT I LOVE TO SEE.
AND YOU'RE STILL HERE DOIN' IT.
YOU'RE STILL ROCKIN' IT OUT.
NICE JOB, GUYS.
THANKS FOR HAVIN' ME.
NEXT UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO VIRGINIA BEACH...
CITRUS PANCAKE.
FOR CITRUS...
IT'S LIKE A SUNSHINE.
AND SOFT-SHELL.
THIS IS A WAY OF LIFE. OH!
OHH, SEE?
NICE.
I'M ABOUT TWO BLOCKS
FROM THE CHESAPEAKE BAY
HERE IN VIRGINIA BEACH
TO CHECK OUT A LOCAL FAVORITE
THAT PEOPLE WALK TO, DRIVE TO,
BIKE TO, EVEN BOAT TO,
FOR TRADITIONAL BREAKFAST
AND LUNCH FAVORITES
WITH A LITTLE
BEACH ATTITUDE SPIN.
THIS IS CITRUS.
ORDER UP FOR TABLE 15.
IT'S THE HOT SPOT OF
VIRGINIA BEACH. GREAT FOOD.
PUMPKIN PANCAKES
WITH PECAN GLAZE.
I'M A BREAKFAST GUY,
AND I LOVE THEIR BREAKFASTS
THAT THEY HAVE HERE.
LEN, HOW'S YOUR
BLOODY MARY?
EXCELLENT, THANK YOU.
WONDERFUL.
(woman) IT'S JUST
SO FRIENDLY.
LANCE AND CHERI MAKE US FEEL
LIKE FAMILY WHEN WE COME IN.
THAT'S OWNERS
LANCE AND CHERI SHORES,
WHO HAVE A LOT
TO BE HAPPY ABOUT
NOW THAT THEY'RE OFF
THE NIGHT SHIFT.
I WAS IN THE NIGHTCLUB
BUSINESS FOR 20 YEARS.
WE GOT TIRED
OF THE 4:00 MORNINGS
AND THAT'S WHERE WE CAME UP
WITH CITRUS.
(Guy) TELL ME ABOUT
THE NAME, CITRUS.
IT ALL WAS THE CONCEPT
OF THE COLORS...
HUES.
SUNNY, WELCOMING,
AND FRESH.
CHERI'S SUNNY PHILOSOPHY
EVEN INSPIRED
THEIR SIGNATURE CAKES.
CITRUS PANCAKES.
(woman) THEY HAVE THEIR CITRUS
PANCAKES, WHICH ARE AWESOME,
THAT YOU CAN'T JUST
GET ANYWHERE.
SHALL I BEGIN?
MAKING CITRUS ORANGE GLAZE.
CITRUS ORANGE GLAZE.
YOU SAY THAT SO NICELY.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SUGAR,
A LITTLE CORNSTARCH, O.J.
WANT ME TO WHISK THAT, OR--
SURE.
THIS IS SKILLED LABOR
FOR ME, I MEAN--
MM-HMM,
THIS IS TOUGH STUFF.
THIS IS GONNA GO
FOR ABOUT 20, 25 MINUTES,
TO KICK IT UP.
JUST TO--JUST TO KIND OF
WAKE THAT CORNSTARCH UP
AND THICKEN IT UP?
EXACTLY.
WE'RE GONNA MOUNT IT
WITH SOME BUTTER.
OKAY.
OKAY, SO YOU'RE GONNA
LET THIS CONTINUE TO REDUCE.
YEP.
AND THEN THIS IS GONNA
GO ON PANCAKES.
AND THAT'S GONNA GO
ON THE PANCAKES.
PANCAKES GONE WILD.
THIS IS THE PANCAKE
BATTER FOR THE--
NO, THIS IS ACTUALLY
A MIXER.
THIS IS A MIXER...
OKAY, OKAY.
AND WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
THE BATTER FOR THE PANCAKES.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH EGGS, BUTTERMILK.
I MIGHT GET YOU TO HELP ME
WITH THIS, WITH THE MUSCLE PART,
PUTTING IT BACK AND FORTH.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
I DON'T KNOW.
I WORKED OUT
AT THE GYM EARLIER.
AND WE'RE GONNA
MIX IT UP.
PUT IT DOWN.
YOU'RE DONE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
DO BAKING SODA,
SALT, BAKING POWDER,
THEN SUGAR...
(normal voice)
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
START IT.
FLOUR--MIX THAT UP.
ALL RIGHT, YOU JUST WANT
TO MIX THIS ENOUGH
TO INCORPORATE IT...
BUT NOT OVERDO IT.
SO WE DO WANT
SOME LUMPS IN THIS.
THEN THE OIL.
(grunting)
AND YOU'RE DONE.
THE BATTER IS READY.
THIS MEANS YOU'RE SERIOUS.
IT'S A 3-, 4-PLUNGER,
5-PLUNGER?
YEAH, WE LIKE, YOU KNOW,
A GENEROUS PORTION.
DON'T LOSE TRACK.
THAT'S FOUR.
AAH.
NOW COME THE SPICES--
CINNAMON, NUTMEG.
WAITIN' FOR THE BUBBLES?
WAITIN' FOR THE BUBBLES.
SO...
WATCHIN' THE BUBBLES.
HOW ABOUT THEM BEARS, HUH?
IT'S HOT. THERE WE GO.
WHOA, WHOA!
OHH.
YAHTZEE. NICE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU READY
FOR SOME PANCAKES?
SUPER-DUPER.
HOW'D YOU COME UP
WITH THE NAME CITRUS?
IT'S LIKE YOU WAKE UP
AND YOU WANT SOMETHING FRESH
IN THE MORNING.
I WANT COFFEE
AND THE SPORTS PAGE.
YOU DO?
NOT FRESH AND INVITING.
AND THEN PLATE--PINEAPPLE
RIGHT HERE IN THE CENTER,
BANANA.
IT'S A SUNSHINE.
THAT'S LIKE A SUNSHINE.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH THIS GLAZE.
THIS IS WHAT MAKES IT
SO GOOD.
(whistles)
YOU READY?
CITRUS GRAVY.
COLD PIZZA,
THE SPORTS PAGE...
AND SOME CITRUS PANCAKES.
AND SOME CITRUS--
SEE?
CITRUS PANCAKES.
YOU'LL BE THINKIN' ABOUT US
ALL THE TIME NOW.
THE GLAZE IS DYNAMITE,
BUT AS SOON AS YOU INCORPORATE
THE BANANA
AND THE PINEAPPLE--
YOU FOOL YOURSELF THAT YOU'RE
HAVING SOMETHING HEALTHY,
BUT ACTUALLY, THAT IS
HALF A BANANA.
IT IS HALF HEALTHY.
YOU GET A LITTLE KISS
OF THE CINNAMON AND NUTMEG.
YEAH.
WAY TO GO.
THANK YOU.
CITRUS SIGNATURE PANCAKES.
THIS IS LIKE DESSERT.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
CRAWFISH BENEDICT
WITH GRITS.
THEY HAVE FRESH FISH
WHEN IT'S IN SEASON.
FRESH FLOUNDER SKILLET.
YOU DON'T HEAR
BREAKFAST AND LUNCH JOINT
AND SAY OYSTERS VERY OFTEN,
OR SOFT-SHELL CRAB.
(Lance) ALL OF OUR SEAFOOD
COMES STRAIGHT FROM THE DOCK.
I NEED A SOFT-SHELL
CRAB BENEDICT, PLEASE.
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
THAT'S DEFINITELY ONE
OF THE THINGS THAT I COME FOR.
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
WE'RE MAKIN'
FRESH HOLLANDAISE.
FIRST WITH OUR EGG YOLKS,
LEMON JUICE,
HOT SAUCE, SALT,
WATER.
GOT IT.
NOW ACTUALLY, GUY,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO HELP ME
POUR IN THIS BUTTER AND MILK.
I DON'T THINK I'M GONNA EVEN
PARTICIPATE. THIS IS YOUR GIG.
YEAH.
THROW THE SUPERCHARGER
ON THAT THING, MAN.
OKAY, TAP OUT. GO.
HERE WE GO.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
YAH, YOU CAN HEAR IT NOW.
IT'S LIKE
A MOTORBOAT ENGINE.
NOW ON LOW HEAT.
(normal voice) OKAY, SO WE
EMULSIFIED ALL THE BUTTER,
AND THE KEY IS, WE STIR
FOR ABOUT 15, 20 MINUTES
TO GET THIS
TO THICKEN UP ON US.
WITHOUT COOKIN' INTO...
RIGHT.
A BIG, OLD NASTY
BATCH OF EGGS.
YEP.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, HAVE A GOOD
TIME. I'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
HOLLANDAISE IS READY.
YES, SIR.
NOW WE'RE MAKIN' THE BATTER
FOR THE SOFT-SHELL.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF WITH
FLOUR, PEPPER, GARLIC...
LAWRY SEASONING.
OUR SEAFOOD SEASONING,
BAKING SODA.
THESE ARE FRESH CRABS
OUT OF SOUTH CAROLINA.
THEY'RE REAL BIG AND THEY'RE
FILLED WITH MEAT.
THESE ARE WHALES.
I BATTER THE CRAB FIRST.
SO A SOFT-SHELL IS A CRAB
THAT'S MOLTED ITS SHELL.
WE DREDGE IT
IN OUR EGG WASH--
AND THEN BACK IN
ONE MORE TIME.
AND THE WHOLE KEY WHEN
YOU LAY IT IN THIS FRYER
IS TO JUST GET THOSE LEGS
SPREAD, AND THAT GETS THAT--
SO IT DOESN'T CLUMP UP.
RIGHT.
THEN YOU CAN SEE IT'S GETTIN'
READY TO POP, SO BE CAREFUL.
THESE CRABS POP 'CAUSE THERE'S
WATER INSIDE THIS CRAB.
RIGHT.
REALLY GET THE POP.
SO THIS ISN'T JUST A BUSINESS
TO YOU. THIS IS A--
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS A WAY OF LIFE. OH!
OHH, SEE?
NICE. GIMME
A LITTLE REPLAY ON THAT.
(distorted voices)
OH, DID YOU SEE THAT?
BE CAREFUL.
RIGHT TO THE NECK.
WHOO!
AND THAT SOFT-SHELL
ONLY TAKES FIVE MINUTES.
LOOK AT THAT. BEAUTIFUL.
YOU BETTER HURRY UP,
BEFORE I EAT ALL THIS.
YEAH, I'M GONNA
POACH THESE EGGS REAL QUICK.
I'M GONNA GET
MY SAUTéED SPINACH
AND PUT OUR TOMATOES
ON THE GRILL
FOR JUST A SPLIT SECOND.
YOU GUYS THOUGHT HE WAS
JUST ANOTHER PRETTY FACE.
(chuckling)
SOME CRAB.
THIS LOOKS WONDERFUL.
LIQUID CHICKEN GRAVY.
MMM.
A LITTLE TOMATO,
A LITTLE SPINACH--MMM.
LOOK AT THE AMOUNT
OF MEAT.
WHEN YOU CALL THOSE WHALES,
YOU'RE CALLIN' THAT OUT
CORRECTLY.
THAT SOFT-SHELL
IS JUST DYNAMITE.
MMM.
THAT'S A TASTY HOLLANDAISE.
I LIKE THAT THERE'S A LITTLE
BIT MORE HOT SAUCE IN THAT.
YEAH.
MMM. ROCKED IT OUT, MAN.
THANK YOU.
AWESOME.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB BENEDICT,
TABLE 1.
VERY YUMMY.
YOU CAN TELL THAT HE HAS ORDERED
THE FRESHEST INGREDIENTS.
THAT MAKES A DIFFERENCE.
(Guy) I SEE A LOT OF BREAKFAST
JOINTS AROUND THE COUNTRY.
WHAT'S THE ATTITUDE?
IT'S FRIENDLINESS.
YOU WALK IN AND IT'S
AN EXPERIENCE.
WE DEVELOP RELATIONSHIPS
WITH THE CUSTOMERS.
AND IT KIND OF MAKES YOUR DAY,
'CAUSE EVERYBODY'S
SO HAPPY AND BRIGHT.
YOU LEAVE HERE FEELING GREAT.
WE LOVE WHAT WE DO.
NICE JOB, YOU GUYS.
REALLY ENJOYED IT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO DOWNTOWN DETROIT...
HERE'S THE CITY WING THING.
FOR SCRATCH-MADE PIZZA...
CROSS BETWEEN PROBABLY
AN AMERICAN STYLE
AND A NEAPOLITAN STYLE.
WITH A THANKSGIVING TOPPING.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
I'M HERE IN DETROIT, MICHIGAN,
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM THE EASTERN MARKET,
TO CHECK OUT A PIZZA JOINT
WHERE THE OWNER GOT
HIS INSPIRATION
FROM A LITTLE VILLAGE THAT HIS
FATHER GREW UP IN, IN ITALY.
HE GOT SO MUCH
INSPIRATION FROM IT
THAT HE NAMED THE JOINT
AFTER IT.
THIS IS SUPINO PIZZERIA.
MARGHERITA GOIN' OUT.
SUPINO'S IS THE BEST PIZZA
ANYWHERE AROUND HERE.
LARGE SUPINO, COMIN' OUT.
NOT NEW YORK PIZZA,
ITALIAN PIZZA.
WHAT MAKES THE PIZZA
SO GOOD?
THE INGREDIENTS.
EVERYTHING'S GREAT. DAVE'S
EXCELLENT AT MAKIN' PIZZAS.
LARGE VERDURE i FUNGHI
COMIN' OUT.
THAT'D BE DAVE MANCINI,
WHO CHUCKED HIS OWN MEDICAL
CAREER OUT THE WINDOW IN 2008
TO OPEN HIS OWN PIZZA JOINT.
WHERE DID YOU BECOME
THE DOUGH AFICIONADO?
UH, WELL, IT WAS ACTUALLY--
SUPINO IS THE NAME OF
MY FATHER'S HOMETOWN IN ITALY,
AND I WENT BACK THERE,
HAD SOME AMAZING PIZZA.
YOU WERE THE TALLEST PERSON
IN THE VILLAGE.
UH, BY A LONG SHOT.
I WAS INSPIRED BY THAT PIZZA.
I THOUGHT IT WAS AMAZING.
OVER THE YEARS, I DEVELOPED
A CRUST ON MY OWN.
IN MY LITTLE KitchenAid MIXER
ON MY COUNTERTOP,
I USED TO MIX A BATCH OF DOUGH
ALMOST EVERY DAY FOR ABOUT
SEVEN YEARS STRAIGHT, TRYIN'
TO GET AT WHAT I REALLY WANTED.
IT'S KIND OF A--
YOU ATE PIZZA
SEVEN YEARS IN A ROW?
MY FRIENDS AND RELATIVES
BENEFITTED FROM IT AS WELL.
ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S
MAKE SOME DOUGH.
WE'RE GONNA START
BY PUTTIN' THE DRY MIX INTO
THE 60-QUART HOBART HERE.
WHAT KIND OF FLOUR
ARE WE USIN'?
WE'RE USIN' BREAD FLOUR,
NICE ELASTICITY.
SO YOU'RE NOT
A DOUBLE ZERO GUY.
I'M NOT A DOUBLE ZERO GUY.
THIS IS NOT NEAPOLITAN.
IT'S MORE LIKE AN EAST COAST
AMERICAN STYLE.
IT BORROWS A LITTLE BIT
FROM THE ITALIAN STYLES, TOO.
A LITTLE BIT OF YEAST--
DRY ACTIVE YEAST.
NOW I'M GONNA MAKE
MY WET MIX--WATER, SALT.
AND THE OIL'S GONNA GO
IN THE WATER HERE, TOO?
YES, SIR,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
ADD THIS.
AND WHEN WILL YOU
USE IT?
TOMORROW.
SO YOU AT LEAST GIVE IT
A 24-HOUR REST.
YOU DO A 24-HOUR--
REALLY DEVELOP SOME
OF THAT YEAST FLAVOR,
BUT WE'LL USE SOME OF THE DOUGH
THAT YOU MADE YESTERDAY.
ABSOLUTELY.
TWICE A WEEK,
DAVE HITS THE EASTERN MARKET
ACROSS THE STREET
FOR THE FRESHEST
INGREDIENTS...
THANKS A LOT, GUYS.
BUT THE KEY TOPPING FOR ONE
OF HIS MOST POPULAR PIES...
LARGE CITY WING THING
GOIN' OUT.
COMES FROM ONE OF HIS BUDDIES.
IT'S A SMOKED TURKEY.
DELICIOUS.
DAVE AND THE CITY WING GUY
COLLABORATED ON THIS.
HERE'S THE CITY WING THING.
NOW ARE YOU REALLY
A CITY WINGS DUDE,
OR DID YOU JUST
GET THE HAT?
IT'S MY SPOT.
THAT'S--OH, THAT'S YOUR SPOT.
YOU'RE THE DUDE. NICE.
YES, SIR.
NICE. BRINE-SMOKED
TURKEY LEGS.
YES, SIR.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME BRAISED TURKEY LEGS
FOR THE CITY WING THING
PIZZA.
OH, SEE IT EVERY DAY.
YEAH. I'M NOT A BIG FAN
OF CHICKEN BREAST ON PIZZA,
AND I'VE BEEN LOOKI''
FOR A POULTRY PRODUCT.
I THROW THE SMOKED
TURKEY LEGS IN HERE.
WE'VE GOT SOME QUARTERED RED
ONIONS, FRANK'S REDHOT SAUCE.
OH, SO WE ARE GOIN' AFTER
A REAL CHICKEN WING FLAVOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF A TANG.
SUGAR. NOW WE'RE GONNA
COVER THIS WITH WATER.
NOW I'VE GOT GARLIC CLOVES,
REALLY MORE FOR FLAVOR.
SO HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET IT GO FOR?
THIS IS GONNA GO FOR ABOUT
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
THEY'RE THE BOMB.
THAT'S TASTY.
THE TURKEY LEG AND THE THIGH--
THEY HAVE SUCH RICH FLAVOR.
YEAH, AND WE WANT
A LITTLE TEXTURE THERE.
WE DON'T WANT IT TO--
YEAH, YOU DON'T WANT IT
TO TURN INTO MUSH.
WE WANT SOME TOOTHNESS
TO THE MEAT. WE DON'T--
TOOTHNESS.
TOOTHINESS. TOOTHNESS.
ONE OF THEM WORDS.
TOOTHINESS.
TOO--TOOTHSOME.
YEAH, YEAH, TOOTHSOME.
220, 221,
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
(imitating lightsaber)
THIS IS REALLY WHERE WE'RE GONNA
SEPARATE THE MEN FROM THE BOYS.
I LIKE THE METHOD
SO FAR,
BUILDIN' THE EDGE.
(laughing)
THAT'S IT.
CHEESE, AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT SAUCE ON TOP.
WE'RE TRYIN' TO KEEP
THAT CRUST NICE AND CRISPY,
SO PUTTIN' THE SAUCE ON TOP
KEEPS THE TEXTURE--
AND A LITTLE GOUDA.
SMOKED GOUDA.
FRESH CUBED MOZZARELLA
OVER TOP OF THAT.
ROASTED GARLIC,
CHERRY PEPPERS,
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH WITH
THE TURKEY WE BRAISED EARLIER.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE...
THAT IS ALL SHE WROTE.
AND WHAT TEMPERATURE
YOU RUNNIN' THAT OVEN AT?
THIS OVEN'S GOIN' 670.
I'VE GOT BRICK LINING THE TOP,
THE BOTTOM, THE SIDES.
THERE'S ALL KINDS
OF THERMAL MASS IN THERE.
THIS DOES NOT GET COLD.
I CAN OPEN AND CLOSE
THIS OVEN ALL DAY LONG.
NOT SOMETHING YOU HEAR EVERY
DAY, BUT TODAY ON TRIPLE "D,"
YOU'VE LEARNED ABOUT
THERMAL MASS.
WITH THAT KIND OF HEAT,
THE PIE BAKES
FOR ABOUT SIX MINUTES
WITH A SPIN MIDWAY
FOR AN EVEN COOK ON THE CRUST.
LOOK AT THAT.
ENOUGH OF THE TOMFOOLERY.
SET UP AND READY TO EAT.
THAT--LET ME TRY
TO EXPLAIN THINGS TO YOU
AS I SHOVE MY FACE WITH IT,
'CAUSE YOU CAN TELL
I DON'T LIKE IT.
IT'S DEFINITELY LIGHT
AND CRISPY.
A CROSS BETWEEN PROBABLY
AN AMERICAN STYLE
AND A NEAPOLITAN STYLE.
MMM.
I GIVE YOU AN "A"
IN THE DOUGH, MAN.
A NICE BLEND BETWEEN
CHEESE AND SAUCE,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE
FROM THE VINEGAR
OF THE SWEET PEPPERS,
CREAMINESS OF THE GARLIC.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS.
(man) IT'S NOT
THANKSGIVING TURKEY
THAT SOMEONE CARVED
FROM THE TABLE.
IT'S SMOKY.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS,
AND IT PAIRS EXCELLENT WITH
THOSE PEPPERS THAT ARE ON THERE.
(Dave) LARGE SUPINO
READY TO GO OUT.
(woman) DAVE IS AN ABSOLUTELY
FEARLESS CHEF
WHEN IT COMES TO MAKING PIZZA.
I DON'T HAVE A FAVORITE.
I NEVER ORDER A PIZZA.
I ALWAYS COME IN HERE AND SAY,
"DAVE, SURPRISE ME."
DO YOU THINK THIS IS SOME
OF THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN?
IT'S DEFINITELY
THE BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
(Dave) I REALLY WANTED TO MAKE
SURE IT WAS SOMETHING SPECIAL,
SOMETHING TO SET ITSELF
APART A LITTLE BIT.
YOU GOTTA COME DOWN HERE
AND TRY THIS PIZZA.
WELL DONE, BROTHER.
REALLY WELL DONE.
THANKS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE RECIPES
TO SOME OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WE'LL BE BACK IN JUST AFTER--
JUST...
(babbles)