HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I SEE YOU TOSSING THAT.
WATCH OUT NOW.
HOMEMADE...
TAKE A LOOKIE-LOO
AT THAT.
AND HOME-BREWED
OUTSIDE INDIANAPOLIS...
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
VERY AUTHENTIC.
SCRATCH COOKIN'...
FRESH SEAFOOD FLOWN IN
FROM LOUISIANA.
ALL THE CAJUN CLASSICS.
(woman) BARBECUE SHRIMP.
BROTHER, YOU GOT IT
GOING ON HERE. MMM, TOP TEN.
IN TAMPA BAY, FLORIDA...
THIS IS OUR FAVORITE PLACE.
A BREWHOUSE...
THE BEER IS GREAT.
PUTTIN' BEER IN EVERYTHING...
THAT MUCH.
FROM MEAT LOAF TO MUSSELS.
MMM. I'M GONNA PASS OUT
EATING THAT.
AND IN CHICAGO...
CORN MASA MEMELAS.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THE LOCAL DIVE...
WE'RE A DIVE
WITH REFINED FOOD.
TAKIN' AUTHENTIC
MEXICAN COOKING...
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY MEXICAN FOOD
I'VE HAD BEFORE.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
SOME MEXICAN CREMA.
DUDE, SERIOUSLY, YOU GO ALL OUT
FOR THIS LITTLE PLATE.
I'M SERIOUS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN MOORESVILLE,
ABOUT 10 MILES SOUTHWEST
OF INDIANAPOLIS,
TO CHECK OUT THE SELF-PROCLAIMED
CAJUN CULINARY EMBASSY
OF INDIANA.
AND I HEAR THESE FOLKS
ARE DOING IT ALL.
THEY GOT THE PO'BOYS,
THE éTOUFFéE, THE JAMBALAYA.
THEY'VE EVEN GOT A MARDI GRAS
PARTY UNDER ONE ROOF.
HERE AT 11 EAST MAIN STREET,
MOORESVILLE,
THIS IS ZYDECO'S 5.
(man) BLACK CAT UP
WITH TAILS.
BLACKENED CATFISH
IS EXCELLENT.
BARBECUE SHRIMP, PLEASE.
FRESH SEAFOOD FLOWN IN
FROM LOUISIANA.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB UP.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT'S KIND OF
MY HOME AWAY FROM HOME.
I'M FROM NEW ORLEANS.
SO IS CO-OWNER...
CUP OF GUMBO UP.
CARTER HUTCHINSON.
I WAS BORN IN NEW ORLEANS,
AND I SPENT ALL MY LIFE
AROUND THE GULF COAST.
AND WHEN HE MOVED UP NORTH
TO MARRY HIS WIFE DEB...
SOFT-SHELL PO'BOY.
THEY OPENED THIS JOINT...
TAILS AND TASSO.
AND STARTED SERVIN' UP
ALL THE CAJUN CLASSICS
HE GREW UP ON...
RED BEANS AND RICE.
I LOVE THE RED BEANS
AND RICE.
CRAWFISH éTOUFFéE.
THIS IS THE ONLY PLACE
I'M GETTING THAT UP HERE.
BARBECUE SHRIMP, PLEASE.
JUST ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
ALL SERVED UP CARTER'S WAY...
30 SECONDS.
WITH A CAJUN SMOKED PORK
CALLED TASSO.
WHAT ARE WE INTO,
BROTHER?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME TASSO SEASONING
FOR THE PORK.
START WITH CAYENNE POWDER...
OKAY.
JUST A LITTLE BIT,
GARLIC POWDER, SALT,
BROWN SUGAR,
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
GOTCHA.
AND MIX THIS UP,
AND THERE'S OUR RUB.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE WANT TO GET
OUR WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
OUR PORK LOIN.
THIS HELPS TENDERIZE
THE MEAT.
HOW LONG DOES IT
STAY IN THERE?
OH, YOU CAN LET IT RUN
A FEW HOURS,
OVERNIGHT, IF YOU'D LIKE.
SO NOW WE GOT OUR TASSO
SEASONING,
AND WE'RE GONNA
DREDGE THE PORK.
NICE LITTLE COATING.
OH, THAT LOOKS GOOD.
OFF TO THE SMOKER?
LET'S GO.
IT'S COLD OUT HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE WE GO.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD
WE GOT IN THERE?
PLAIN, OLD HARDWOOD.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA RUN?
UH, ABOUT TWO HOURS.
NICE.
LOOK AT THAT. OH.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
DON'T DROP IT, PLEASE.
OKAY.
CHOP IT UP?
YES.
THAT'S THE SEASONING
FOR OUR SHRIMPS.
THIS IS A REAL SIMPLE RECIPE--
A POUND OF BUTTER...
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
SOME TABASCO--
ABOUT A TEASPOON.
GOOD.
SO JUST A TEASPOON,
RIGHT UNDER, SHORT OF 1/2 CUP.
RIGHT.
IT'S GONNA BE
SO HOT.
GARLIC,
SOME BAY LEAF,
CAYENNE...
OH, PLEASE.
YOU'RE LOOKING
AT A DEAD MAN.
PAPRIKA, RED PEPPER SEED...
I GOTTA BE ABLE
TO EAT IT, CARTER.
SOME THYME.
A LITTLE SHRIMP OIL?
RIGHT, OKAY,
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR SHRIMPS.
NO, I'M SORRY.
THOSE ARE SEA PONIES.
HEAD AND ALL.
THE WHOLE THING.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR
GREEN ONION, A LITTLE LEMON.
MMM.
WE CAN'T FORGET
OUR TASSO.
GO, GO FOR THE TASSO.
LET THAT COOK FOR A MINUTE.
FLIP IT WITH MY TONGS.
GOT OUR
BARBECUE SHRIMPS DONE.
PLATE THESE PUPPIES UP.
TASSO ON TOP OF THAT.
POUR THAT BARBECUE SAUCE.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF IT.
MMM. BROTHER, YOU GOT IT
GOING ON HERE.
YOU GOT IT GOING ON
BIG TIME.
MMM! THE FLAVOR...
IS EVERYWHERE.
YOU GET SPICE,
CITRUS, GARLIC.
MM-HMM.
THE SMOKED TASSO--YOU WANT
TO TALK ABOUT LOUISIANA.
MMM. BROTHER, IT SEEMS LIKE
WE'RE RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET.
THAT IS ROCKIN'.
TOP TEN.
THANK YOU.
(woman) AND BARBECUE SHRIMP.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
AND THE SHRIMP?
I LOVE IT.
THE FOOD IS AMAZING.
(Carter) ANDOUILLE PO'BOY.
BUT WHAT MAKES THE FOOD
EVEN BETTER
IS THE ENVIRONMENT
THAT IT'S IN.
WHAT'S UP?
DEB AND CARTER
ARE THE GREATEST.
STEVE MIGHT
BITE MY ARM OFF.
ARE THEY AS CRAZY
AS THEY SEEM, MAN?
OH, HONEY, YES.
THERE YOU GO, DARLING.
AND THE FOOD IS INCREDIBLE.
TAILS AND TASSO.
CARTER--AN AMAZING CHEF.
HE HAS SUCH PASSION.
HE WHIPS UP THE CAJUN MAGIC.
I GOTCHA.
CRAWFISH AND TASSO
IN AN ALFREDO SAUCE--
IT'S FABULOUS.
JAMBALAYA.
OH, IT'S TO DIE FOR.
HE'S EVEN SCRATCH-MAKING
THAT CAJUN STANDARD--BOUDIN.
IT'S BASICALLY
SAUSAGE FILLED WITH RICE
AND A LITTLE OF PORK LIVER
IN IT--IT'S VERY, VERY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER,
SO WHAT ARE WE INTO?
WE'RE MAKING THE BOUDIN.
BOUDIN.
RIGHT.
IT LOOKS LIKE PORK STEAK WITHOUT
THE BONE AND THE HOLY TRINITY.
EXACTLY RIGHT.
OUR BELL PEPPER,
OUR ONION, CELERY.
OH, GO BIG WITH THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LET'S DO THAT.
GARLIC, SOME BAY LEAF,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
AND THYME.
WE ADD WATER,
AND WE'RE GONNA LET THAT COOK
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
GOT IT.
NOW IF YOU HAND ME
THAT LIVER.
CAN'T DO IT.
SURE YOU CAN.
NOPE.
DON'T DO IT.
WELL...
DON'T EVEN
PUT IT NEAR ME.
OKAY.
IT'S LIKE MY KRYPTONITE.
THERE'S OUR LIVER.
AND IF YOU COULD
HAND ME THE WATER.
TOYING WITH ME
WITH THE LIVER.
POUR THAT IN THERE.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA BOIL THAT
LIVER DOWN, TOO, HUH?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE LIVER'S COOKED UP.
RIGHT.
THE PORK'S COOKED UP.
NOW WE GRIND IT UP
TO MAKE THE SAUSAGE.
RIGHT. LET'S CUT
THE LIVER FIRST.
SO HERE, I GOT YOU
A LITTLE PIECE YOU CAN TRY.
OH, NO.
WE GOT OUR LIVER CUT,
PORK DONE OVER HERE.
GRIND IT ALL TOGETHER.
RUN IT ALL THROUGH.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'RE DONE WITH THAT.
YOU'RE GONNA KILL
THIS LITTLE THING.
NEXT, WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME RICE.
ADD SOME GREEN ONIONS
TO THIS, PARSLEY.
ISN'T THAT PRETTY?
WE GOT THAT MIXED UP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE STOCK.
WE WANT TO GET THIS WET.
THE LIVER WASN'T IN THE STOCK,
WAS IT?
MAYBE A TOUCH.
CARTER.
ADD SALT AND PEPPER.
MIX IT UP.
ALL RIGHT,
NOW WE'RE GONNA SPOON THIS
IN THE STUFFER.
PUT THIS HERE
LIKE THIS.
ALL RIGHT,
HERE WE GO.
SO THERE'S YOUR LINK.
TWIST IT.
JUST KEEP
ROLLING IT OUT.
TAKE A LOOKIE-LOO
AT THAT.
THAT'S IT.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
GRILL IT.
BOUDIN ON.
FOR A MINUTE OR TWO.
GIVE IT A FEW LITTLE POKES.
THAT HELPS THE STEAM ESCAPE,
SO IT WON'T EXPLODE.
DON'T WANT TO LOSE
THE LIVER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE GOT SOME SAUTéED ONION
AND BELL PEPPER.
OKAY, THAT SHOULD BE DONE.
PUT THAT ON A PLATE.
ONE SIDE
OF MY BRAIN SAYS,
"IT SMELLS GOOD,
IT'S GONNA TASTE AWESOME."
THE OTHER SIDE SAYS,
"LIVER, LIVER, LIVER."
CREOLE MUSTARD.
THAT'S IT.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM, SUPER TENDER.
THE FLAVOR AND THE FAT
FROM THE PORK,
THE HERBS AND THE SPICES,
THE LIVER FLAVOR--
IT'S GOT A SILKINESS
TO IT.
LOVE THAT MUSTARD
UP ON TOP.
A LOT OF GREAT SAUSAGE--
MMM--OUT OF LOUISIANA.
I GIVE YOU CREDIT
FOR MAKING YOUR OWN, MAN.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
THERE'S YOUR BOUDIN, BABY.
YOU CAN TELL IT'S SOMETHING
THAT WAS MADE VERY FRESH.
YOU CAN TELL CARTER
MADE IT HIMSELF.
RED BEANS WITH TASSO,
PLEASE.
IT'S NOT THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU FIND IN INDIANA.
I THINK, ONCE YOU CROSS OVER
THE THRESHOLD HERE,
YOU'RE IN LOUISIANA.
YOU DEFINITELY GOT THE ENERGY
AND THE ATTITUDE HERE.
THANKS.
THANK YOU, BABY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
NEXT UP...
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO TAMPA BAY, FLORIDA,
WHERE IT'S TAP...
THE BEER IS GREAT.
TO TABLE.
(woman) MEAT LOAF.
MMM. (whistles)
OH, I DIG
ROLLIN' INTO TAMPA BAY.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
GREAT WEATHER,
REALLY COOL PEOPLE,
AND SOME TRULY MEMORABLE
TRIPLE "D" LOCATIONS--
I MEAN, TED PETERS SMOKED FISH
AND KEEGAN'S.
WELL, WE'RE IN A HISTORICAL AREA
KNOWN AS YBOR CITY
TO CHECK OUT A BREWHOUSE
THAT'S NOT JUST HANDCRAFTING
THEIR BEERS,
THEY'RE HANDCRAFTING
THEIR FOOD.
THIS IS
TAMPA BAY BREWING COMPANY.
(man) MOOSEKILLER BEER.
THE BEER IS GREAT.
(woman) SHEPHERD'S PIE.
GOOD BEER, GOOD FOOD.
(man) WINGS, TABLE 10.
(man) THE HEART AND SOUL
OF THIS BUSINESS
IS THE FAMILY'S APPRECIATION
FOR BEER.
IT ALL STARTED IN ENGLAND.
I GREW UP IN PUBS.
THE PERFECT PLACE
FOR OWNER VICKI DOBLE...
WHAT ABOUT THE MOOSEKILLER?
TO LEARN THE FAMILY BUSINESS
FROM HER DAD.
THE FOOD HAS TO BE GOOD,
AND THE BEER LINES
HAVE TO BE PERFECT.
TODAY, HER SON DAVID'S
GOT A HANDLE ON THE BEER.
YOU COME TO CHECK
ON MY POURING?
WELL, YEAH.
IT'S MY JOB.
AND CHEF RYAN KELLY...
RIGATONI UP.
HAS BROUGHT AN ALL-STAR LINEUP
TO THE MENU.
AND THIS IS, LIKE,
A HEAVY-HITTER, BIG-TIME,
BIG-LEVEL CHEF.
I LIKE TO DO COMFORT FOOD
WITH KIND OF A GOURMET TWIST.
LIKE LOADING UP BREAD PUDDING
WITH CHOCOLATE AND CHERRIES...
IT'S A GREAT DESSERT.
OR STUFFING BACON BURGERS
IN HOMEMADE DOUGH.
BURGER BOMB, TABLE 5.
HE'S EVEN DRESSING UP
THE CLASSIC MEAT LOAF
WITH A HOME-BREWED DEMI-GLACE.
IT'S NOT YOUR MOM'S MEAT LOAF.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY DELICIOUS.
WE'RE STARTING OUT WITH OUR
BARLEY WINE MEAT LOAF TODAY.
IS IT BARELY WINE,
OR IS IT BARLEY AND WINE?
IT'S THE BARLEY WINE,
BECAUSE THAT'S ACTUALLY
THE MOOSEKILLER BEER.
THAT'S CONSIDERED
A BARLEY WINE.
WHAT ALCOHOL
IS IN THAT,
LIKE, 12%, 15%?
YEAH, 12.1%.
IT'LL DROP A MOOSE,
HENCE THE NAME, YEAH.
START WITH THE PORK,
GROUND BEEF, EGGS.
A LITTLE BINDER.
YEAH.
ONIONS, MUSHROOMS...
CELERY, CARROTS...
KETCHUP, CHICKEN BASE,
MMM, FRESH ROSEMARY,
A LITTLE BASIL...
YEAH.
A LOAD OF GARLIC.
A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
OREGANO...
A TOUCH OF SALT?
YES, SIR. THYME.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES
IS THYME.
YEAH.
A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER.
FINISH UP
WITH THE PANKO.
THEN WE FIRE IT UP.
USING THE MIXER
IS THE WAY TO GO.
RIGHT, YEAH,
WE JUST TRY TO BASICALLY
GET IT INCORPORATED
AND CALL IT A DAY.
OKAY.
WE HAVE, LIKE, A MEAT LOAF PAN.
WE LACE THAT PAN UP WITH BACON.
AND WE PUT
THE MEAT LOAF IN.
ALL RIGHT.
SARAN WRAP, FOIL,
PLACE IT IN THE OVEN.
SO THE MEAT LOAF
IS COOKED OFF, 350?
YEAH.
SO WHILE THAT'S COOLING,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SAUCE?
SURE THING.
WE JUST START OUT
WITH BUTTER, BACON.
THROW IN SOME WHITE ONION,
BUTTON MUSHROOMS.
LET THOSE SWEAT DOWN.
YEAH.
AND THEN DEGLAZE IT
WITH THAT MOOSEKILLER?
YES, SIR.
IT'LL PROBABLY FLAMBé,
IT'S SO HIGH IN ALCOHOL.
RUN A NITROMETHANE DRAG RACE,
DRAG CAR ON THAT.
(laughs) YEAH. YEAH.
SO WE'LL ADD THE DEMI.
A LITTLE TOUCH
OF SALT.
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
FINISH IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE BUTTER.
YEAH.
NOW WE CUT
THE MEAT LOAF.
YEAH. FLOP IT OUT
LIKE THAT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A LUSCIOUS LOG.
LET ME CUT THESE
INTO 10 OUNCES.
SLAB.
YEAH, 10-OUNCE PIECES.
I MEAN,
LOOK AT THE SIZE OF THAT.
YOU'RE TALKING
OVER 1/2 POUND.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON THE GRILL.
GET IT NICE AND HOT.
GET THAT OFF THE GRILL.
OVER HERE ON THE WHITE CHEDDAR
MASHED POTATOES WITH THE DEMI.
GOTTA GET
ALL THE GOOD STUFF.
DO NOT TEASE ME
WITH THIS.
JUST POUR IT ON.
THERE YOU GO. ATTABOY.
MMM.
THEN WE'LL FINISH OFF
WITH THE BUTTERMILK
FRIED ONION RINGS.
I DIG IT.
CHECK THAT OUT.
MMM.
WOW, THERE'S A LOT
GOING ON THERE.
THE SAUCE IS SPOT ON.
MMM.
YOU REALLY GET THAT BEER.
I'M JUST GETTING
THE RICHNESS OF IT, MMM,
BUT COUNTERBALANCED
WITH THE SWEETNESS
OF THE ONIONS AND MUSHROOMS
AND THE BACON FAT.
YEAH.
GREAT MASHED POTATOES.
NICE AND CREAMY. MMM.
ONION RINGS
ARE PRETTY GANGSTER.
MMM, LOOK HOW TENDER.
IT JUST FALLS APART.
MMM. IT'S DYNAMITE.
THANK YOU.
REALLY. (whistles)
(woman) MEAT LOAF.
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE
MEAT LOAF.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
HELLO, SIR.
SHEPHERD'S PIE.
CEDAR SALMON.
WHERE ELSE CAN YOU GO
WHERE THEY BREW THEIR OWN BEERS
AND USE THEIR BEERS
IN EVERYTHING THAT THEY MAKE?
WE'RE ON BEER.
EVERY DISH, I TRY TO FIND A WAY
TO PUT BEER IN IT.
EVEN--GET THIS--HOT WINGS
MADE WITH FRESH-BREWED BEER
AND HARD CIDER.
CIDER WINGS, TABLE 10.
THE CIDER BRINGS OUT A LOT
OF FLAVOR IN THE HOT SAUCE...
WHICH GIVES IT
SUCH A UNIQUE TASTE.
NOW I DON'T PUT IT
ON MY BUSINESS CARD,
BUT I AM
A WING AFICIONADO.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE MAKING BREWHOUSE
CIDER WING SAUCE.
DIG IT.
WE START OUT WITH BUTTER,
CRYSTAL HOT SAUCE.
EVERYBODY'S GOT
THEIR FAVORITE.
I'M A BIG FAN OF CRYSTAL.
OKAY.
HONEY.
AND WHAT BEERS
DO WE THROW IN?
REDEYE AND CIDER.
SO YOU'RE GONNA LET THAT
SIT THERE,
LET THE BUTTER MELT,
LET IT REDUCE JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GET OUR WINGS
READY TO GO IN THE FRYER.
SO WE START OUT WITH FLOUR,
CORNMEAL BREADING...
NICE LITTLE TEXTURE
TO THAT, YEAH.
LEMON PEPPER.
WE DIDN'T DREDGE THIS.
SO WE'RE NOT
GETTING A CAKEY...
NO.
THIS IS JUST PUTTING
A LITTLE CRISP ON IT.
YEAH.
RIGHT IN THE FRYER.
OIL IS RUNNING 350.
PULL IT. WHAT'S NEXT?
BLUE CHEESE.
LOOKS LIKE A LOT
OF BLUE CHEESE.
YEAH, YEAH.
SOUR CREAM, MAYONNAISE.
COPIOUS AMOUNTS.
GARLIC.
YEAH, WORCESTERSHIRE,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER, SALT...
REALLY?
A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR.
AND THEN WE
FINISH IT HERE
WITH A MIXTURE OF VINEGAR
AND BLUE CHEESE.
JUST TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE EXTRA KICK.
MIX THAT UP.
LET IT SET
FOR A COUPLE HOURS.
OKAY, SO THERE'S OUR SAUCE
MADE WITH BEER.
YES, IT'S EVERYWHERE.
I'M STAYING AWAY.
I SEE YOU TOSSING THAT.
WATCH OUT NOW.
(whistles)
LADLE UP SOME
OF OUR BLUE CHEESE NOW.
SOME THICK SPACKLE.
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. WOW.
THAT LITTLE BIT OF BREADING
THAT YOU PUT ON THERE,
ESPECIALLY THE CORNMEAL PART,
MM-HMM,
GIVES A NICE
LITTLE TEXTURE,
AND IT HOLDS ON
TO SOME OF THAT SAUCE.
YEAH.
IT'S NOT BEER WING SAUCE,
MMM, BUT IT ACCENTUATES IT.
YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD WING, MAN.
MM-HMM.
I HAVE
YOUR CIDER WINGS.
JUICY, TENDER, EXCELLENT.
AND THE SAUCE IS REALLY
TANGY, REALLY SWEET.
THEY JUST COME OUT PERFECT
EVERY TIME.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
I HEAR YOU GOT A MUSSEL DISH
THAT YOU'RE GONNA USE WITH BEER
AND THAI IN A POT.
YEAH.
THIS, I GOTTA SEE. COME BACK,
TRIPLE "D" IN TAMPA BAY.
WELCOME BACK
TO TAMPA BAY BREWING COMPANY.
I'M HANGING OUT
WITH MY BUDDY RYAN HERE.
NOW THIS DUDE
HAS GOT A PRETTY TOUGH TASK
OF GETTING BEER
OR TRYING TO GET BEER
INTO A LOT
OF THE RECIPES.
BARLEY WINE MEAT LOAF.
CIDER WINGS, TABLE 10.
WINGS ARE THE BOMB.
MEAT LOAF IS THE BOMB.
THIS ONE, I GOTTA BE
HONEST WITH YOU, MAN--
MUSSELS AND BEER?
YEAH.
YOUR MUSSELS.
THE CURRY MUSSELS
IS AMAZING.
THE WILD WARTHOG
CURRY MUSSELS.
WILD WARTHOG
YEAH.
OKAY.
SO WE'LL START OUT
WITH PRETTY MUCH LIKE
A TRADITIONAL ROUX, SOME BUTTER.
WE'LL ADD MIREPOIX
TO THAT--CARROTS, CELERY,
POBLANO PEPPERS,
WHITE ONION.
SO A TRADITIONAL MIREPOIX,
AND THEN YOU WENT A LITTLE
SOUTHWESTERN ON ME.
SO WE'RE GONNA GO WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF BAY LEAF, CURRY POWDER.
WE'RE JUST GONNA LET THAT
KIND OF COOK IN A LITTLE BIT.
MMM.
OKAY, NOW THE FLOUR.
BUILD THAT ROUX.
THE THING THAT WORKS SO WELL
WITH THIS DISH AND THE BEER
IS THE YEAST THAT'S USED
TO MAKE THIS BEER
HAS A LOT OF NATURAL
CLOVE AND BANANA FLAVOR IN IT,
SO IT JUST IS KIND OF LIKE
A NATURAL FIT FOR CURRY.
REGULAR MILK.
YEAH, JUST REGULAR OLD MILK,
A LITTLE TOUCH OF VINEGAR.
THROW THAT LITTLE ACID
COMPONENT RIGHT IN THERE.
YEAH.
SO THE SAUCE IS DONE
AND...
A POUND OF MUSSELS.
OKAY.
SO WE'LL PUT THIS
OVER THE TOP.
START TO LISTEN HERE--
LITTLE, COUPLE JUMPS AND POPS.
YOU'D JUMP AND POP, TOO,
IF I PUT YOU IN THERE, RIGHT?
(laughs)
START IN WITH THE TOMATOES,
GRILLED ONIONS,
GARLIC, BUTTER.
WHAT A HOT PAN.
YEAH.
WE WILL PUT 'EM OUT NOW
WITH SOME WARTHOG.
THAT MUCH?
YEAH.
OH, I CAN SMELL IT.
COCONUT MILK, CLAM JUICE,
SRIRACHA.
WOW.
MY MOUTH IS FULL-ON WATERING
RIGHT NOW.
ADD OUR CURRY SAUCE.
MMM. I WANT
TO STICK MY HAND IN THERE.
SALT, WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF UDON NOODLE
THAT GOES IN THE BOTTOM
OF THIS,
RIGHT ON TOP OF THAT.
WHAT A DISH.
FINISH THAT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF GREEN ONIONS.
OKAY.
MMM. DUDE,
THE BROTH IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
CREAMY, RICH,
THE MUSSELS ARE TENDER.
MMM. I'M GONNA PASS OUT
EATING THAT.
(laughs)
YOU KNOW HOW TO MAKE
AN ORCHESTRA
OF FLAVOR GO ON, MMM,
GETTING THE BEST OUT OF ALL
THE DIFFERENT INGREDIENTS.
APPRECIATE IT.
THAT'S PRIME TIME, BRO,
PRIME TIME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
(man) I HAVE YOUR MUSSELS.
THANK YOU.
THE FLAVOR IS AMAZING.
THE MUSSELS ARE TENDER
AND THICK AND JUICY,
AND THEY'RE JUST INCREDIBLE.
MUSSELS, TABLE 10.
IT'S GOT
A GREAT PRESENTATION.
THIS IS OUR
FAVORITE PLACE OF ALL.
HERE'S YOUR
FISH AND CHIPS.
I LOVE COMING HERE.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE FOR YEARS.
IT'S REALLY POPULAR, BUT IT'S
ALSO A LITTLE BIT OF A SECRET,
WHICH WE PREFER.
YEAH.
NOT ANYMORE. NOT SO MUCH
ANYMORE. THANKS, GUY.
NOT ANYMORE.
MEAT LOAF, 51.
(woman) WE LOVE THE BEERS.
WE LOVE THE ATMOSPHERE.
IT MAKES US FEEL LIKE
WE'RE FAMILY.
YOU'RE GREAT.
IT'S A GOOD PUB.
NO, I'D GIVE IT--I'D REALLY
SAY IT'S A GREAT PUB.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
COMING UP NEXT...
PICK UP FLAUTAS, GUYS.
THE NORTH SIDE OF CHI-TOWN...
WE'RE A DIVE
WITH REFINED FOOD.
FOR SMALL MEXICAN PLATES...
I CAN'T SAY I'VE HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
WITH BIG-TIME FLAVOR.
FLAVOR JETS TURNING ON,
ACTIVATE.
I'M HERE IN THE NORTH SIDE
OF CHICAGO
IN AN AREA KNOWN
AS LAKEVIEW EAST
TO CHECK OUT A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S IN A BASEMENT
AND I HEAR IS SERVING UP
SOME RIGHTEOUS, FARM-TO-TABLE,
SMALL-PLATE,
MEXICAN-INFLUENCED FOOD.
THIS IS CHILAM BALAM.
FLAUTAS IN THE WINDOW.
OH, I LOVE THIS PLACE.
CORN MASA MEMELAS.
EVERYTHING
IS ORGANIC AND FRESH,
AND YOU CAN TASTE
THE DIFFERENCE.
(woman) LAMB IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY MEXICAN FOOD
I'VE HAD BEFORE.
I CAN'T SAY I'VE HAD
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE CLASSICALLY TRAINED
CHEF CHUY VALENCIA...
30 SECONDS ON THE FLAUTAS.
HAS A STYLE ALL HIS OWN.
KIND OF LIKE A PUNK ROCK TWIST
ON MEXICAN FLAVORS
WITH MOSTLY LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
I GOT A TAMALE
COMING UP, GUYS.
WHEN YOU COME IN HERE,
YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT
THE KIND OF PRESENTATION
THAT YOU GET.
MUSHROOM POTATO SOUP.
WE'RE A DIVE
WITH REFINED FOOD.
YEAH, LIKE
CHILI-GLAZED PORK RIBS,
SHIITAKE MUSHROOM EMPANADAS,
OR HIS TAKE ON A CLASSIC
MEXICAN SNACK FOOD...
PICK UP FLAUTAS, GUYS.
IT'S A DELICIOUS THING.
THEY DON'T OFTEN
COME COVERED IN SAUCE.
AND TOPPED
WITH HOMEMADE CHEESE.
WE'RE MAKING QUESO FRESCO.
REALLY?
YEAH.
IT'S FRESH CHEESE.
RIGHT.
DO YOU MAKE ALL
YOUR OWN QUESO FRESCO?
YEAH.
THIS IS FOR THE FLAUTAS.
OUT OF ALL THE THINGS
HE COULD BE DOING
IN THIS TINY KITCHEN, THIS IS
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF WORK.
AN EXTRA LABOR OF LOVE.
LET'S GO.
FIRST IS WHOLE MILK.
NOW WE'RE ADDING BUTTERMILK
TO THIS WHOLE THING.
AND THE FRESH...
LIME JUICE.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE?
THIS TAKES ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF, SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE JUST TRYING
TO DISTRIBUTE THE HEAT
THROUGHOUT
THE REST OF THE MILK.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S STARTING
TO RISE UP.
IT'S LIKE
A CHEESE CLOUD.
TAKE IT OUT.
SET IT INTO
SOME CHEESECLOTH?
MM-HMM, AND THEN OVERNIGHT,
WE'RE JUST GONNA BUNDLE IT UP,
PUT IT IN THE CONTAINER
WITH A SOUP BOWL ON TOP.
REALLY GONNA PRESS IT.
LET'S GO, QUESO.
AWESOME.
I'M JUST GONNA
UNRAVEL THIS GUY.
WE ARE RIGHT
INTO THE REAL DEAL.
JUST KIND OF
LIGHTLY CRUMBLE IT.
ARE WE PANNING FOR GOLD?
THERE'S GOLD IN THEM DARN HILLS.
SO NOW WITH A LITTLE SALT.
YEP.
GIVE IT A GOOD LITTLE MIX.
LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH.
CHEESE IS READY TO GO.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA BUILD
THE SAUCE FOR THE FLAUTAS.
DRIED CHIPOTLE CHILIES--
WE JUST TOAST THEM TO GET SOME
OF THE ESSENTIAL OILS
WORKING OUT OF THE CHILIES.
RECONSTITUTE 'EM WITH
A LITTLE MORE WATER?
YEAH, JUST HOT WATER.
SO NOW THEY STEEP.
SO THEY'RE NICE AND SOFT,
READY TO BE BLENDED.
HOT WATER.
OKAY.
WE GOTTA BREAK DOWN THE STEM
THAT WAS STILL THERE
AND ALL OF THE SEEDS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE PURéE
AND FRY IT IN DUCK FAT.
(imitates quacking)
SO THEN WE GOT
A STRAINER.
WE'RE MAKING A SAUCE,
AND WE'RE PUTTING
A LITTLE FRY ON IT.
IT TAKES A LITTLE BIT
OF THE BITTERNESS OUT,
AND THEN I JUST GOT
A BIG WHISK HERE.
AND THAT'S GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE WHILE TO DARKEN UP.
OKAY.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN STOCK.
AND NOW ROASTED TOMATILLOS.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE READY JUST
TO KIND OF SEASON THE SAUCE--
WHITE ONIONS
CHARRED ON THE GRILL...
OKAY.
ROASTED GARLIC, BLACK
PEPPERCORNS THAT WE'VE TOASTED,
MEXICANO OREGANO,
OUR EPAZOTE,
WHICH IS AN ANTI-CARMINATIVE
MEXICAN HERB.
ANTI-WHAT-A-WHAT?
CARMINATIVE...
OH, YES.
SO IT GETS RID OF
THE FLATULENCE IN BEANS.
OH.
IT'S THE ANTI... (mumbles)
(mumbles)
A LITTLE MORE CHICKEN STOCK,
A LITTLE BLEND.
SO THIS FUNKY
LITTLE SEASONING MIX
IS GONNA GET POPPED
INTO THIS?
YEAH.
SUCH A REFINED SAUCE.
AND WHISKING NOW.
KOSHER SALT,
UNREFINED SUGAR, STIR.
LET THIS BOIL
FOR 30, 40 MINUTES.
LET IT CONTINUE TO REDUCE
AND LET IT SET.
YES.
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
CHICKEN FILLING
FOR THE FLAUTA--
A LITTLE RICE BRAN OIL,
WHITE ONION,
JUST ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT.
HELP THE CARAMELIZATION
A LITTLE BIT FASTER.
SOME POBLANO CHILIES,
ROASTED CARROTS...
THE SHREDDED CHICKEN.
YEP. I'M JUST GONNA
STIR THIS A TINY BIT.
NOW THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAUCE
INCORPORATED INTO THIS.
EXACTLY.
LET THIS MIXTURE COOL, AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA ROLL THE FLAUTAS.
RIGHT, RIGHT.
WE GOT THIS SPECIAL
LIME-TREATED TORTILLA
TO DIP IN THE HOT OIL.
MAKE IT PLIABLE.
NOW WE COME TO THE MIXTURE.
IT'S A BOUNTIFUL FILL.
WE'VE GOT IT.
WE'RE READY TO DO OUR ROLLING.
BOTH ENDS THIS WAY.
WE JUST GO STRAIGHT THROUGH,
AND THEY DON'T OPEN.
WOW.
WE'RE JUST GONNA POP
THESE GUYS IN THE FRYER.
NOW THEY'RE FRIED
AND GOLDEN BROWN.
WE JUST LIKE SPLITTING THEM
DOWN THE MIDDLE
SO EVERYBODY
CAN KIND OF SHARE.
TOP 'EM WITH SOME
OF OUR CHIPOTLE SAUCE.
WE GOT SOME NAPA CABBAGE
AND CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR.
FLAVOR JETS TURNING ON,
ACTIVATE.
WE JUST DO A LITTLE BIT
OF CHARRED CARROT.
WE MAKE
OUR PICKLED RED ONIONS,
SOME MEXICAN CREMA.
DUDE, SERIOUSLY, YOU GO ALL OUT
FOR THIS LITTLE PLATE?
I'M SERIOUS.
NICE LITTLE DUSTING OF THE QUESO
FRESCO, AND LAST, CILANTRO.
IT'S READY.
MMM-MM-MMM.
REALLY NICE HEAT.
MMM.
GREAT CRUNCH,
GREAT FLAVOR.
THE VINEGAR
OF THE ONIONS,
THE FAT COMPONENT COMES THROUGH
WITH THE CHEESE, MMM,
THE LITTLE BIT
OF THE SLAW CRUNCH.
REALLY ALIVE,
REALLY EXCITING. MMM.
IT'S JUST BING, BING, BING,
BING. GREAT JOB. IT'S FANTASTIC.
HERE'S YOUR FLAUTAS
WITH CHICKEN.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S UNLIKE ANY OTHER FLAUTAS
OUT THERE.
FLAUTAS, PICKUP.
I LIKE THAT IT'S EASY TO KIND OF
SHARE WITH YOUR FRIENDS.
AND THAT'S KIND OF
THE WHOLE POINT.
SMALL PLATES ALL KIND OF MEANT
TO SHARE AT THE TABLE.
SO YOU ORDER, LIKE,
TWO OR THREE ENTRéES AT A TIME,
AND GIVE EVERYTHING
A TRY.
AND HOW MANY ITEMS
DO YOU HAVE ON THE MENU?
WE HAVE 16.
EVERYTHING IS AMAZING.
RAVIOLI EMPANADA,
TABLE 4.
WE HAVE THE PORK RIBS
RIGHT HERE.
BUT I ALWAYS END UP
ORDERING THIS.
CORN MASA MEMELAS.
THE MEMELAS HERE IS GREAT.
AND THEN THE BEANS ON THE INSIDE
ARE VERY DELICIOUS.
I LOVE 'EM.
THEY KEEP ME COMING BACK.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NOW?
CORN MASA MEMELAS,
WHICH ARE BASICALLY LIKE SOPAS,
KIND OF LIKE A WAHACAN
VERSION OF SOPA.
OKAY.
WE GET FRESH MASA
IN EVERY DAY.
OKAY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA A TAKE
PALM OIL SHORTENING
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
BAKING POWDER,
KIND OF START
KNEADING IT.
GIVE ME THE SHOW.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A BALL
ABOUT YEA BIG AND THEN MAKE
BASICALLY, LIKE,
A PINCHED LITTLE CUP.
SO YOU LINE THESE UP
AND THEN FRY 'EM?
EXACTLY.
TOTAL FRY WORKOUT.
AND THEN WHAT ARE WE
GONNA FILL IT WITH?
ORGANIC REFRIED BLACK BEANS.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE DOING
SOME HOT WATER, THE EPAZOTE.
I DO A LITTLE
TINY BIT OF OIL.
I BOIL THESE
A LITTLE OVER TWO HOURS.
COOL IT DOWN, AND THEN
WE'LL GET IT INTO THE REFRIED.
EXACTLY.
GOT IT.
LET'S STRAIN
THE BLACK BEANS.
OKAY.
WE GOT A SMOKING HOT PAN.
I START DOING OUR ONIONS.
OUR RICE BRAN OIL, WHITE ONION,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
LET THESE ONIONS GO
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
SOMETHING THAT'S MAKING
AN APPEARANCE IS AVOCADO LEAF.
NICE.
WE'RE GONNA JUST TOAST THEM.
NOW WE'RE READY TO BLEND.
FRIED GARLIC...
AND SOME BEAN WATER.
YEAH. EXACTLY, YEAH.
LOW SPEED.
OKAY.
THAT DOESN'T TAKE MUCH. NOW
LET'S TOSS OUR BEANS IN HERE.
AND NOW ALMOST IMMEDIATELY,
WE GO IN WITH OUR
AVOCADO LEAF LIQUID.
OKAY, SO YOU JUST KIND OF
LET THIS HEAT UP,
CONTINUE TO MASH IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, LET THIS
BOIL AND THICKEN.
OKAY.
THESE ARE
THE FRIED MEMELAS.
SOME BLACK BEAN
OVER HERE.
NICE.
THIS BEAUTIFUL
AGED GOAT CHEESE.
SO NOW WE GOT
OUR ARBOL SAUCE,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
TAKE SOME OVER THE TOP,
A LITTLE
POBLANO VINAIGRETTE
OVER THE PEA
AND SUNFLOWER SHOOTS.
SALAD ON TOP.
AND THAT'S IT.
MMM.
THE MEMELAS
NICE AND TENDER.
THE BEANS
HAVE TEXTURE AND CHEW.
MMM. YOU GOT A LOT
OF DEPTH IN THERE,
A LOT OF DIVERSITY
IN THE FLAVOR.
BUT WHO'S LEADING THE WAY?
MMM, ARBOL SAUCE.
THAT TIES IT TOGETHER.
NICE JOB, MAN.
(man) CORN MASA MEMELAS.
IT'S GOT A GREAT FLAKY,
BISCUIT FEEL TO IT.
MM-HMM.
THE FLANK STEAK
AND GUAJILLO.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHY
I LIKE COMING HERE.
IT'S SOMETHING DIFFERENT
EVERY TIME.
ORDER UP IN THE WINDOW.
EVERYTHING YOU GET
IS JUST AMAZING.
THANK YOU, MAN.
WE HAD A GREAT TIME.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
TO GET ALL THE RECIPES
OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
NOW IT ALL MAKES SENSE. ISN'T
THAT RIGHT, CRAZY LIBRARIAN?
(man) ALL RIGHT, BIG GUY.
HA HA!