HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I FEEL GOOD ABOUT ME.
BAR FOOD...
SOMEBODY ORDERED
THE PORTER.
AND BONBONS...
CRUNCHY, FRIED GREATNESS.
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
IT'S JUST LIKE
COMING HOME.
THE THIRD-GENERATION
JOINT...
NONNIES MINESTRONE.
WHERE THEY'RE
SERVING UP SLIDERS...
THEY'RE AMAZING.
AND ROCKIN' THE RAVIOLI.
THIS IS ONE OF THE BEST
RAVIOLIS I'VE EVER HAD.
IN ASTORIA, QUEENS...
I JUST ABSOLUTELY
LOVE THIS PLACE.
THE DIVE BAR...
THE FOOD COMPLETELY
CONTRADICTS THAT.
BREAKING OUT,
WHAT ELSE...
MMM.
VEGGIE BURGERS.
REALLY GOOD
VEGGIE PATTY.
AND IN INDIANAPOLIS...
EXCITING CREATIONS.
THE NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE...
(woman) GOOD FOOD.
DOING COMFORT FOOD...
SHREDDED BEEF SANDWICH.
GONE WILD.
LOOKS LIKE
A MEAT SUNDAE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
I'M HERE AT A COOL
LITTLE TOWN CALLED GEYSERVILLE
IN THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
WINE COUNTRY
TO CHECK OUT A PLACE THAT
I KINDA HAVE SOME HISTORY WITH.
I IMAGINE A COACH
FEELS REALLY PROUD
WHEN ONE OF HIS PLAYERS
TURNS PRO,
'CAUSE THAT'S HOW I FEEL
WHEN ONE OF MY GUYS
THAT'S WORKED WITH ME
IN MY RESTAURANTS
VENTURES OUT
TO OPEN HIS OWN PLACE.
THAT BRINGS US HERE
TO CATELLI'S.
HERE YOU GO, FOLKS.
WE GOT YOUR FOOD READY.
WHERE NICK CATELLI...
WHAT DO WE GOT, D.C.?
AND HIS SISTER DOMENICA...
SPAGHETTI, D.C. SAUCE.
HAVE COME HOME.
MY NONNY AND NONNO,
VIRGINIA AND SANTI,
OPENED CATELLI'S IN 1935.
AND NICK AND DOMENICA
FIGURED...
TABLE 11.
THEY'D BE RUNNING IT SOMEDAY.
'CAUSE WE'VE ALWAYS
DREAMT OF IT.
BUT THE FAMILY LOST
THE BUSINESS BACK IN '91.
HELLO, MAMA.
HI, PAPA.
ONCE THAT HAPPENED, MY SISTER
AND I WERE VERY ADAMANT--
WE WILL OPEN THIS AGAIN, AND IT
WILL BE THE FAMILY BUSINESS.
AND IT IS,
SINCE THEY TOOK OVER
A YEAR AGO...
SLIDERS HERE, SWEETIE.
AND STARTED SERVING
THE OLD CATELLI CLASSICS.
NONNIES MINESTRONE.
HOW DOES
THE FOOD TASTE?
IT'S DELICIOUS.
(woman) CHICKEN SAUTé SEC.
I JUST ABSOLUTELY
LOVE IT.
RAVIOLI COMING UP!
WITH THE BUTTER
AND GARLIC SAUCE,
IT'S DELICIOUS. MMM.
IT'S THIN. IT'S COOKED
TO PERFECTION.
ALL MADE BY HAND EVERY DAY.
YEAH.
SERIOUSLY?
JUST LIKE GRANDMA CATELLI.
WE ARE MAKING
THE RAV FILLING.
THE PORK BUTT.
SO YOU CUT THE STRIPS.
THE PORK GOES
INTO THE GRINDER.
I WANT THAT
AS A RINGTONE.
SO NEXT, WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SLURRY
THAT SEASONS THE PORK
WITH CHARDONNAY,
WHOLE BLACK PEPPERCORNS,
FENNEL SEED.
PRINCIPAL ITEMS
IN SAUSAGE.
YES. RED PEPPER FLAKES,
FRESH THYME,
A TON-LOAD OF GARLIC,
FRESH GROUND NUTMEG,
AND THEN SALT.
WE DON'T HAVE A LID FOR OUR
BLENDER ANYMORE FOR SOME REASON.
IN TRUE CATELLI'S STYLE.
YEAH. SHE'S READY
TO ROLL.
OKAY.
THAT GOES IN HERE.
THEN WE JUST SQUISH IT.
AND THIS IS GOING IN THE FRIDGE
FOR TWO DAYS.
TO REALLY LET
THOSE FLAVORS COME OUT.
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT IN THE WORLD
ARE WE INTO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA ROAST OFF THE MEAT,
BIG BEEF CHUNKS.
CHICKEN.
SKIN ON. AND THEN HERE'S
OUR HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE.
IF YOU CAN GRAB
THE OLIVE OIL...
GOT IT.
AND GIVE ME A GOOD DOUSE
AND DRIZZLE ON HERE
AND SALT AND PEPPER,
AND WE'RE GONNA ROAST THIS.
GOING AT 450
FOR HOW LONG?
30 TO 40 MINUTES.
WE HAVE TO MIX
ALL OUR VEG.
OKAY.
ONION, CELERY, GARLIC,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SWISS CHARD.
LOOK AT THIS.
SUCH GREAT TEXTURE,
GREAT FLAVOR.
SALT AND PEPPER, YEP.
AND THEN THAT'S
GONNA GO IN...
INTO THE OVEN?
FOR ABOUT 40 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA
DUMP THE MEAT...
AND THE JUICES.
INTO THERE.
OH, IT SMELLS AWESOME.
SO THE BREAD GETS MIXED IN.
LET'S GET ALL THE VEG
IN THERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE PECORINO...
OKAY.
AND PARMESAN, THYME.
THYME.
BASIL.
ITALIAN PARSLEY?
YES.
THIS SMELLS SO GOOD.
ROSEMARY, SALT,
SOME PEPPER, SAGE,
AND THEN EGGS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
BACK TO THE GRINDER.
YES.
NOW I CAN'T HOLD THIS
AND BE OVER THERE
EATING ANY OF THAT
AT THE SAME TIME.
THAT'S PART OF THE PLAN.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND YOU CAN TASTE IT
AT THIS POINT.
MMM. YOU PUT THAT
IN A FLIP-FLOP,
THAT WOULD TASTE GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE MAKING THE DOUGH
FOR THE RAVIOLI.
PUT THE EGGS IN,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA POUR
THE DOPPIO ZERO FLOUR.
SUPERFINE FLOUR.
SO MIX IT UP, PULL IT OUT,
KNEAD IT A LITTLE BIT MORE.
LET IT REST.
YES. AND WE'RE GONNA
CUT OFF A PIECE, ROLL IT OUT.
HOW MANY TIMES IS THIS
GONNA GO THROUGH?
11.
YOU GOT 27 HOURS
IN A DAY HERE?
SO THIS IS GONNA
BE ROUND 1.
CRANK IT DOWN
AND JUST KEEP GOING.
OKAY, WE'RE GOING
DOWN TO ONE,
AND THIS IS WHEN WE'RE GONNA
READ THE NEWSPAPER.
CAN YOU READ IT?
THAT'S NUTS.
SO THE MEAT FILLING.
THIS IS LIKE THERAPY.
I FEEL GOOD ABOUT ME.
OKAY, WE'RE MOISTURIZING.
LAY THIS ON TOP.
PRESS DOWN.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR LITTLE SQUARES,
SO THEN YOU CAN
MAKE IT PRETTY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
QUICK-FREEZE 'EM.
AND PLEASE, AFTER THAT
CAN WE EAT?
YES. LET'S BOIL THE RAVS.
WHEN THEY FLOAT TO THE TOP,
WE'RE GONNA PULL 'EM OUT.
WHAT FANTASTIC-NESS
ARE YOU TOSSING THAT IN?
BUTTER, GARLIC, SALT, PARSLEY,
AND A PINCH OF PARMESAN CHEESE.
MANGIA.
WOW. SO TENDER, DELICATE,
AND SO RICH.
SMALL, DAINTY, HANDMADE
PERFECTION IS WHAT THIS IS.
THIS IS ONE OF THE BEST RAVIOLIS
I'VE EVER HAD.
(woman) WE HAVE CATELLI'S
MEAT RAVIOLIS.
PASTA IS DONE PERFECT.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
IT'S THIN, AND YOU
CAN TASTE THE MEAT.
CATELLI'S RAVIOLI,
BUTTER, GARLIC.
THEY'RE DOING
A GREAT JOB.
AND HOW IS EVERYTHING GOING
SO FAR THIS EVENING?
IT'S GREAT TO SEE THEM
COME BACK...
IS THERE MORE WINE
GOING ON HERE?
AND RETAIN
THE OLD-STYLE ITALIAN.
WITH A LITTLE
SOMETHING EXTRA.
THE RABBIT WORKING.
I CALL OUR FOOD ITALIAN-
INFLUENCED CALIFORNIA FOOD.
LOCAL LAMB,
BALSAMIC-ROASTED GRAPE.
I HAVE AN ITALIAN FAMILY,
BUT I GREW UP HERE.
KIND OF OLD-SCHOOL, BUT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF A MODERN TWIST.
SAUCING THE SLIDERS.
YEAH, LIKE MEATBALL SLIDERS
IN RED SAUCE.
THEY'RE AMAZING.
IT'S A COMBINATION
THAT REALLY WORKS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THIS IS OUR
FAMOUS TOMATO SAUCE.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, HOT PEPPER FLAKES.
AND I WANT THE GARLIC
TO GET SOFT.
SO IT'S LOW AND SLOW
ON THE HEAT.
ORGANIC TOMATOES.
CALIFORNIA?
YES.
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT?
YEP.
AND HOW LONG WILL YOU
JUST LET THIS COOK?
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE MEATBALLS
FOR THE MEATBALL SLIDERS.
ORGANIC BEEF
AND OUR HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE.
OKAY.
CAN YOU GIVE ME
THE RICOTTA CHEESE?
THAT'S WHAT KEEPS THIS
NICE AND MOIST.
THIS IS MY MIX OF PANKO
AND BREWER'S YEAST
AND A LITTLE GARLIC
IN THERE.
REALLY? A LITTLE
BREWER'S YEAST IN THERE?
YEP. SO THEN WE--
ONION, GARLIC.
ONIONS, GARLIC.
THIS ONE'S PARM,
AND THEN ITALIAN PARSLEY.
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
THYME, SALT...
OKAY.
PEPPER AND AN EGG IN THERE.
MIX ALL THIS TOGETHER.
SO SHOW ME THE SIZE
OF THE MEATBALL.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SMALLER
THAN A GOLF BALL.
PUT 'EM ON THE SCALE.
YOU WEIGH EACH ONE?
OUNCE AND A HALF?
YEP.
BAKE 'EM FIRST?
NO. WE DO 'EM
IN A CAST-IRON SKILLET.
HANG ON A SECOND.
WE COOK 'EM RAW
TO ORDER.
YOU COOK THEM RAW
TO ORDER...
YES.
FOR EVERYONE THAT GOES
TO THE DINING ROOM?
YES!
SO WE START 'EM IN OLIVE OIL.
THIS IS AN ORDER OF SLIDERS.
AND NOW THEY HAVE A NICE,
BEAUTIFUL, GOLDEN COLOR ON 'EM,
SO WE'RE GONNA POP 'EM
INTO THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT ANOTHER FOUR
TO FIVE MINUTES.
AND THEN WE PUT
OUR SAUCE ON.
RIGHT IN.
LOVE IT.
THEY GO ON THE BUNS.
AND THEN WE--WE'RE GONNA POUR
THE SAUCE OVER 'EM
AND CHEESE 'EM UP
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF PARSLEY
TO TOP IT OFF.
NICE. NICE!
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
DELICIOUS MEATBALL.
YOU CAN TASTE THE INGREDIENTS.
THE RICHNESS OF THE BEEF--
IT MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH
WHEN YOU EAT IT.
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU COOK
SOMETHING TO ORDER,
THE TEXTURE JUST--
THERE'S NO REPLACING THAT.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE A SUPERSTAR.
(Nick)
JACKS MEATBALL SLIDERS.
THIS IS
ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
GOOD FLAVORS. THEY'VE GOT
A NICE BLEND OF THE SPICES.
VERY TENDER
AND FANTASTIC.
IT'S A GREAT RESTAURANT.
HOMEMADE RAVIOLI UP.
JUST LIKE COMING HOME.
IT'S PERFECT.
AND IT STILL FEELS LIKE FAMILY,
JUST KIND OF A NEW GENERATION.
TO FAMILY.
IT'S A DREAM COME TRUE.
I DIDN'T THINK THAT I WOULD
SEE IT HAPPEN IN OUR LIFETIME.
I'M VERY PROUD OF BOTH OF YOU,
SO... OKAY?
THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE IT.
YOU GOT IT.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
(woman) LAMB RIBS
WITH TZATZIKI.
WE'RE HEADING
TO QUEENS, NEW YORK...
IT'S SO GOOD.
FOR VEGGIE BURGERS?
MMM.
I ALREADY FEEL HEALTHIER.
I'M GONNA GO FOR A RUN.
♪♪♪
I SO DIG NEW YORK CITY.
I MEAN, EVERY TIME
I ROLL INTO TOWN,
I LEARN SOMETHING NEW.
SO HERE I AM
IN ASTORIA, QUEENS,
WHERE THEY HAVE GOT THE OLDEST
BEER GARDEN IN THE CITY.
BUT--BUT THEY--
BUT I KNEW THAT.
WHAT I DIDN'T KNOW
IS THAT RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET,
THEY'VE GOT A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S SERVING UP
SOME RIGHTEOUS BAR FOOD.
WELCOME TO THE SPARROW TAVERN.
(woman) LAMB RIBS
WITH TZATZIKI.
THE SPARROW IS KIND OF
A ROCK 'N' ROLL DIVE BAR.
THE FOOD COMPLETELY
CONTRADICTS THAT.
IT'S SO GOOD.
SLOPPY PORK SANDWICH.
THE SLOPPY PORK SANDWICH
IS FULL OF FLAVOR.
GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
PROBABLY THE BEST
GRILLED CHEESE
THAT YOU CAN GET
IN NEW YORK CITY.
GRILLED CORN ON THE COB.
THEY PUT THE CHEESE ON TOP.
IT TASTES REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
BABY MIXED GREENS
WITH A SKIRT STEAK.
YOU CAN'T GET THIS, YOU KNOW,
AT ANY RESTAURANT.
WE STARTED OUT JUST
AS A DIVE BAR, BASICALLY.
THEN THREE YEARS AGO,
OWNER EVANGELOS ROUMELIOTIS...
ED.
UPPED THE ANTE...
WE STARTED COOKING,
STARTED WORKING ON RECIPES,
ADDED MORE AND MORE THINGS
ON OUR MENU.
AND BROUGHT IN
CHEF PABLO GARCIA...
(Pablo) HERB FRIES.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
AT A FOUR-STAR RESTAURANT.
SERVING UP
FOUR-STAR BAR FOOD.
THE BURGERS, OF COURSE,
ARE AMAZING.
THE BIFTEKI BURGER--
EXTREMELY FLAVORFUL.
BACON AND BRIE BURGER--
FANTASTIC.
AND EVEN...
(Pablo) VEGGIE BURGER UP.
THE VEGGIE BURGER'S
AWESOME.
IT DOESN'T TASTE ANYTHING LIKE
YOUR GENERIC VEGGIE BURGER.
IT'S SOMETHING
JUST ENTIRELY DIFFERENT.
ALL RIGHT, PABLO,
BRING A VEGGIE BURGER.
YES, SIR.
OKAY.
WE WANT TO START
WITH THE CARROTS.
SOME SHREDDED CARROTS.
ZUCCHINI, BARLEY.
NICE LITTLE BARLEY
FOR GOOD TEXTURE AND THAT.
CORN, GREEN PEAS,
SOME POTATOES.
SOME BINDER, GOT IT.
I LIKE THIS IDEA
WITH THE MASHED POTATOES.
SCALLIONS.
THERE WE GO.
YOU MIX IT UP.
YEAH.
A LITTLE SALT.
SALT AND PEPPER,
PANKO BREADCRUMB,
RED PEPPERS,
SOME MUSHROOMS.
GRILLED MUSHROOMS, RIGHT?
YES. AND BROWN RICE.
YOU'VE GOT EVERYBODY
IN THE POOL ON THIS ONE.
I'LL MIX IT UP.
A LOT OF VEGGIES.
LET IT SIT
FOR AN HOUR.
LET IT KIND OF WORK TOGETHER
A LITTLE BIT. OKAY.
EXACTLY, WITH THE PANKO.
NOW IT'S READY?
YES, IT IS READY.
SO LET'S MAKE THE PATTIES NOW.
6 OUNCES.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL
ON THE TRAY.
SUCH CARE AND DETAIL
HE TAKES.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA PUT 'EM
ON THE FLATTOP?
NO, ON THE TRAY,
AND THEN WE BAKE.
WE BAKE 'EM FIRST?
YES.
WHAT ARE
WE MAKING NOW?
THE SAUCE FOR THE VEGGIE BURGER,
SWEET CAYENNE MUSTARD.
SWEET CAYENNE MUSTARD?
YES.
MAYONNAISE, CAYENNE.
(whistles slowly)
MUSTARD.
OKAY.
AND MAPLE SYRUP.
MAPLE SYRUP.
SO MIX IT UP.
OKAY. CAN I TRY IT?
YEAH.
OH, THAT'S CRAZY.
YOU MAKE THAT UP?
YEAH.
WATCH OUT. PULL 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT.
SO I PUT ON THE FLATTOP
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
PUT A LITTLE CRUST
ON 'EM.
EXACTLY.
OKAY. AND WHAT DOES IT
GET SERVED WITH?
PITA BREAD AND FRIES.
LOOK AT THAT. IS THAT
ROSEMARY AND ONIONS IN THERE?
YES, IT IS.
I HAVEN'T
SEEN THAT BEFORE.
OKAY.
SALT, PEPPER, PARSLEY.
SHAKE IT.
OH.
SO WE HAVE IT HERE.
THEN WE PUT
FRISéE LETTUCE.
ROSEMARY AND ONION-
COOKED POTATOES
WITH A MAPLE-CAYENNE
MUSTARD MAYO
STUCK WITH A VEGGIE PATTY
INTO A WHOLE-WHEAT PITA
WITH A LITTLE
FRISéE LETTUCE--
THE THING EXACTLY YOU'D EXPECT
TO FIND IN A DIVE BAR.
DRESS IT UP, CLOSE IT UP,
AND SHOVE IT UP. MMM.
I LOVE IT. HMM. THIS IS
A REALLY GOOD VEGGIE PATTY,
SUPER MOIST FROM THE ZUCCHINI
AND THE CARROTS
AND THE MASHED POTATOES,
GOOD TEXTURE FROM THE BARLEY
AND THE RICE.
THERE'S A LOT OF CRUNCH
IN THIS WHOLE-WHEAT PITA.
MMM. I ALREADY
FEEL HEALTHIER.
I'M GONNA GO FOR A RUN.
SEE YA IN A MINUTE.
(laughs)
HERE'S YOUR
VEGGIE BURGER, ED.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
(man) I'M NOT
A VEGGIE BURGER.
JOIN THE CLUB.
THIS VEGGIE BURGER
JUST MIGHT CONVERT YOU.
IT ROCKS, DOESN'T IT?
IT'S THAT GOOD.
AND THE HERBED FRIES
ARE PHENOMENAL.
A LITTLE BIT OF ROSEMARY
COOKED WITH SOME ONIONS--
I'M RIPPING THAT IDEA OFF
FO' SHO.'
(Ed) SOME OF THE BEST FRIES
I'VE EVER HAD.
I'VE HAD SOME
GOOD FRIES.
THOSE ARE
ROCKIN' FRIES.
EVERYTHING IS JUST
OF A HIGHER QUALITY.
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW IT
FROM OUTSIDE.
WELL, THAT'S THE BEAUTY
OF THIS PLACE.
IT'S GOT A BEAT-DOWN
KIND OF FEEL TO IT,
AND THEN YOU LOOK AT THE MENU,
AND THE FOOD'S EXTRAVAGANT.
(Pablo) MUSSELS IS UP.
THE MUSSELS ARE AMAZING.
GRILLED APPLE SANDWICH.
AWESOME.
LAMB RIBS ARE READY.
AND THIS CROWD-PLEASER
IS DONE GREEK STYLE.
THE FRESH HERBS
AND THE TZATZIKI.
IN A DIVE BAR?
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
PABLO.
YES.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING
NOW, BROTHER?
TZATZIKI SAUCE
FOR THE LAMB RIBS.
TZATZIKI SAUCE?
WHAT ARE YOU--
ARE YOU SURE
YOUR NAME'S "PABLO"?
(laughs)
IT'S "PABLO BATALI."
OKAY.
OKAY, SO YOGURT...
OH, I LIKE GREEK YOGURT.
CUCUMBER,
DILL, SOME GARLIC.
A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER.
SALT AND PEPPER.
THERE WE GO.
YOU MIX IT UP.
YES. AND WE FINISH
WITH OLIVE OIL.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL
BRINGS IT ALL TOGETHER.
AND MIX AGAIN.
SO LET THAT CHILL.
LET THE FLAVORS MARRY.
SO THERE'S
THE LAMB RIBS.
SALT AND PEPPER FIRST.
THAT'S A GOOD JOB
ON THE FRESH CRACKED PEPPER--
MAKES ALL THE DIFFERENCE
IN THE WORLD.
NOW THE OTHER SIDE.
THYME NOW...
A LITTLE THYME.
ROSEMARY.
OKAY.
THE LAST THING--
LEMON ZEST.
NICE JOB. LOOK AT HIM.
ALL THE LITTLE DETAILS--
NOT LEAVING ANYTHING
ON THE PAN.
THEN WE COVER.
WHAT TEMPERATURE ARE WE
GONNA COOK IT AT?
250.
250 DEGREES.
HOW LONG?
4 HOURS.
FOUR HOURS. OKAY.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE RENDER.
YOU WANT TO CARVE FIRST.
(laughing) OHH,
MY DAD WOULD LOVE THIS.
READY?
READY.
ONTO THE GRILL.
A LITTLE CHAR ON 'EM.
SO LET'S PUT SOME
TZATZIKI SAUCE ON HERE.
PRETTY GENEROUS THERE.
(whistles)
THEN PUT A LITTLE BIT
OF JUICE.
HE DOESN'T MISS A BEAT--
GOES BACK TO THE PAN, GETS
A LITTLE BIT OF THE DRIPPINGS.
AND THEN CHIVES.
OKAY.
FRESH PEPPER.
THERE YOU GO, MAN.
YOU DIDN'T COOK WHEN YOU CAME
TO THE UNITED STATES?
AND THEN YOU JUST PICKED
ALL THIS UP?
YES.
IT'S A GOOD-LOOKING
LAMB RIB
WITH TZATZIKI SAUCE.
(laughs) OH!
IT'S TENDER, SUPER JUICY,
FALLS OFF THE BONE. MMM.
AND THE TZATZIKI SAUCE--
MMM.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING,
BUT YOU'RE MAKING
SOME GREAT BAR FOOD.
YOU DON'T SEE THAT EVERY DAY.
GOOD LAMB RIBS, MAN. MMM.
(woman) LAMB RIBS.
EXTREMELY DELICIOUS.
(Ed) THE MEAT
JUST FALLS OFF THE BONE.
THE FLAVOR
IS JUST BURSTING.
(woman) IT'S AMAZING.
SOMEBODY ORDERED
THE PORTER.
NOT YOUR NORMAL BAR FOOD.
(Pablo)
GRILLED SWISS CHARD.
I JUST ABSOLUTELY
LOVE THIS PLACE.
(Guy)
THIS IS A FUNKY JOINT.
YOU'VE GOT PABLO JUST KNOCKING
IT OUT--WHAT'S UP, PABLO?
(bell dings)
THAT GUY IS AWESOME.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
GREAT PLACE, MAN.
NEXT STOP...
EXCITING CREATIONS.
WE'RE HEADING
TO INDIANAPOLIS...
ORDER UP--TACOS.
FOR COMFORT FOOD...
ASIAGO FRIED CHICKEN.
WITH ATTITUDE.
MUSHROOM RAGOUT
IS WHAT MAKES IT.
♪♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN INDIANAPOLIS,
IN AN AREA KNOWN
AS SOUTH BROAD RIPPLE,
OR "SoBro"
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT A MOTHER-AND-DAUGHTER TEAM
STARTED OUT
AS A CATERING KITCHEN
WITH A LITTLE RESTAURANT
ON THE SIDE.
BUT THINGS QUICKLY CHANGED,
AND IT BECAME A RESTAURANT
WITH A LITTLE CATERING
ON THE SIDE
ONCE PEOPLE GOT
A TASTE OF ZEST!
ORDER UP--TACOS.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA FIND
THESE TACOS ANYWHERE ELSE.
(woman) CRèME BRûLéE
FRENCH TOAST UP.
EXCITING CREATIONS.
HERE'S YOUR
3-NAPKIN BURGER.
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT,
BUT IT'S FANTASTIC.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
THE FLAVOR THAT YOU GET
OUT OF IT IS UNIQUE.
YEAH, UNIQUE,
LIKE VALERIE VANDERPOOL.
SALMON AND SCALLOPS.
I USED TO BE
IN A ROCK BAND.
I BET YOU DID.
THEN SHE OPENED THIS JOINT
WITH HER MOM CAROL.
HI, HOW YA DOING?
DID YOU EVER
SEE HER PERFORM?
OH, ALL THE TIME.
♪ I LOVE TRIPLE "D" ♪
♪ SO COME AND TAKE YOUR TIME
AND EAT WITH ME ♪
(record needle scratches)
IS IT THE SAME ENERGY
AND ENTHUSIASM
SHE PUTS INTO COOKING?
YEAH,
SHE HAS A PASSION.
FOR CRANKING OUT ORIGINAL HITS,
LIKE THE BEEF SANDWICH...
(Valerie)
SHREDDED BEEF'S UP.
TOPPED WITH SOMETHING VALERIE
CALLS "BLUE CHEESE MOUSSE."
DELICIOUS.
IT'S JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME BLUE CHEESE MOUSSE--
MAYONNAISE, SOUR CREAM.
PETRI DISHES
OF SOUR CREAM.
THAT'S RIGHT. SHALLOTS.
WE BLOOMED SOME GELATIN
IN LEMON JUICE.
THAT'S WHAT'S GONNA LET
THE MOUSSE SET UP.
OKAY.
CRUMBLED BLUE CHEESE,
AND THEN PROCESS.
WE LIKE IT TO STAY
JUST A SLIGHT BIT CHUNKY.
YOU WANT TO KNOW IT'S BLUE
CHEESE AND NOT JUST SCHMEAR.
YES, EXACTLY.
WE HAVE WHIPPED CREAM.
CREAM THAT WE'VE
ACTUALLY WHIPPED?
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
AGAIN, EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE.
SO THIS GETS FOLDED.
IT'S A NICE AND LIGHT MOUSSE,
BUT HEAVY FLAVOR
GOING WITH THE SHREDDED BEEF...
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THE ONION JAM.
MM-HMM.
WE USE CHUCK, TRIM SOME
OF THE EXTRA FAT OFF.
SLICE IT ABOUT 2
OR 3 INCHES.
(imitates knife squeaking)
OKAY.
NOW ARE WE GONNA
SEASON THIS?
OLIVE OIL, SALT,
AND PEPPER.
OAKY.
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO SEAR IT.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
MM-HMM, PRETTY, HUH?
FIVE MINUTES ON THIS SIDE,
ALL NICE AND CARAMELIZED.
WE'LL SEAR IT
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
RED WINE AND BEEF BROTH.
PUT THE LID ON IT
SO WE CAN BRAISE IT.
GONNA GO IN THE OVEN?
THREE HOURS. ARE YOU READY
TO MAKE SOME ONION JAM?
♪ ONION JAM ♪
HOW DO YOU MAKE IT?
OLIVE OIL, YELLOW ONIONS,
AND RED ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
TO HELP 'EM CARAMELIZE.
AND PEPPER.
YO, GO AFTER IT.
IT TAKES ABOUT HALF AN HOUR
FOR THESE TO COOK DOWN.
SO THE ONIONS ARE NICE
AND CARAMELIZED.
YEAH, THEY ARE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
RED WINE, BALSAMIC VINEGAR,
CRUSHED THYME, AND SUGAR.
THIS IS GONNA
CONTINUE TO COOK DOWN,
AND THIS IS GOING ON THAT
SHREDDED BEEF SANDWICH.
YEAH.
AND HERE'S THE ALREADY-COOKED
MEAT COMING OUT.
OKAY, SO THE MEAT ISN'T
COMPLETELY SHREDDED.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
CHUNK-A-SHRED.
YEAH. AND THEN THIS IS
THE BROTH THAT IT WAS COOKED IN.
WE HAVE IT
IN A FAT SEPARATOR.
THOSE LITTLE THINGS
WORK COOL.
I LOVE IT.
HEAT IT UP WITH JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF ITS OWN BROTH.
YEP. BAGUETTE WRAPPED IN FOIL
TO KEEP THE JUICE IN.
GOING OLD CHICAGO BEEF
STYLE RIGHT THERE.
AND THEN...
LOOK AT YOU BACKHAND-SERVING
THE SAUCE.
ONION JAM,
OUR BLUE CHEESE MOUSSE.
LOOKS LIKE A MEAT SUNDAE.
NOW IT'S GONNA GO
INTO THE CONVECTION OVEN.
HOLY MOLY, SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
SHREDDED BEEF SANDWICH.
NICE.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
MMM. THAT'S BIG FLAVOR.
THE ONION, THE SHREDDED BEEF,
AND A NICE ROLL--
THIS IS A SANDWICH
THAT TASTES LIKE A MEAL.
BUT THE BLUE CHEESE MOUSSE--
THAT'S WHAT TIES IT ALL
TOGETHER. GREAT JOB. KILLER.
THANK YOU.
SHREDDED BEEF SANDWICH.
(man) THE WAY VALERIE
MAKES IT,
IT'S JUST AWESOME.
(Valerie)
COMING IN HOT.
JUST A LITTLE TOUCH
OF SEASONING.
(man) THE BLUE CHEESE
JUST SETS THE SANDWICH OFF.
TILL YOU TRY IT,
YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD,
AND IT'S VERY DOWN-HOME.
SHORT RIBS UP!
THINGS WE'RE ALL FAMILIAR WITH,
BUT WITH A LITTLE SLANT ON IT.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
THE FOOD?
DOWN-HOME GOES UPTOWN.
LIKE THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC...
FRIED CHICKEN UP!
VALERIE'S DOING
WITH AN ASIAGO CHEESE CRUST
AND A THAI MARINADE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
THAI MARINADE.
BUT FOR ASIAGO CHICKEN.
MM-HMM. WE DON'T PLAY
BY THE RULES HERE.
NO.
DARK BROWN SUGAR,
TERIYAKI SAUCE--
STIR THAT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
SOME ORANGE JUICE CONCENTRATE,
NOW THE WATER,
AND THEN FRESH GINGER.
ADD THE GARLIC.
MMM.
DO YOU GUYS JUST CHUG IT
AFTER YOU'RE DONE, OR...
"AUGUSTUS, NO!"
UM, JUST KIND OF
MIX IT.
OKAY, PUT THE CHICKEN BREASTS
IN THERE.
BONELESS SKINLESS?
YEAH.
THIS WILL GO INTO
THE WALK-IN OVERNIGHT.
OKAY.
SO THIS IS
THE ASIAGO BREADING.
OKAY.
CORNMEAL,
PANKO BREADCRUMBS,
KOSHER SALT,
MEXICAN OREGANO.
OH. YOUR RECIPE?
ALL THIS STUFF IS MINE.
DRY MUSTARD, PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
SHREDDED ASIAGO,
WHICH IS LOCAL.
I'LL MIX IT.
OKAY, NOW ARE WE GONNA DO
THE FLOUR AND EGG WASH?
WE ARE.
THERE SHE GOES.
OKAY, YOU READY?
CHICKEN IN THE FLOUR.
UNSEASONED, ALL-PURPOSE?
YEAH. THEN EGG,
THEN INTO THE BREADING.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO COOK
THE CHICKEN.
FIRST, OLIVE OIL.
INTO THE PAN.
JUST BROWN IT.
JUST A LITTLE BROWN.
SEE, ISN'T THAT PRETTY?
OOH! THAT'S GOLDEN
FUNK-A-CRUNCHA.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN THE OVEN.
THE SAUCE THAT GOES
ON TOP OF THE CHICKEN
IS CALLED
WILD MUSHROOM RAGOUT.
OKAY.
OLIVE OIL, MINCED SHALLOTS,
MINCED GARLIC,
AND THEN WE GOT
THE WILD MUSHROOMS.
DIG IT.
SALT, PEPPER.
WAIT TILL THE MUSHROOMS COOK
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
ADD OUR RED SAUCE.
AND THE RED SAUCE IS?
IT'S TOMATO-BASED,
SORT OF MARINARA-ISH.
TASTY?
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
LET IT COOK DOWN A LITTLE.
TAKE THE CHICKEN
OUT OF THE OVEN.
LOOK AT THAT. WOW.
MUSHROOM RAGOUT--
THAT GOES ON TOP.
A LITTLE PARSLEY.
THE RAGOUT
SMELLS AWESOME.
AND THERE YOU GO--
ASIAGO FRIED CHICKEN.
MMM.
LOOK AT THE NICE, BIG CRUNCH
THAT'S ON THE OUTSIDE OF THAT.
THIS HAS A LOT
OF ASIAGO FLAVOR,
BUT IT'S GOT
TRUE FRIED CHICKEN CRUNCH.
HANDMADE FROM SCRATCH--
I LIKE THE CORNMEAL IN THERE.
I LIKE THE TEXTURE
OF THAT.
MUSHROOM RAGOUT
IS WHAT MAKES IT.
ASIAGO FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S AWESOME.
IT'S MOIST,
GOT A LOT
OF SPICE TO IT.
CHICKEN'S DONE NICELY.
I LOVE THE ASIAGO CHEESE
BREADING.
AND VALERIE'S PUTTING
THAT BREADING TO WORK
ON ANOTHER ZEST! ORIGINAL...
TOMATO BONBON.
A KIND OF
A DEEP-FRIED TOMATO...
THERE'S A NICE LITTLE
SURPRISE IN THE MIDDLE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
MMM.
GOOD, OLD, DOWN-HOME,
CRUNCHY, FRIED GREATNESS.
♪♪♪
AT ZEST!
EXCITING FOOD CREATIONS
IN INDIANAPOLIS...
WILD HIBISCUS JELL-O SHOTS.
OWNER VALERIE VANDERPOOL...
EGGPLANT WELLINGTON.
IS WORKING FROM
HER OWN COOKBOOK.
TOMATO BONBONS.
IT HAS A NICE LITTLE
SURPRISE IN THE MIDDLE.
TOMATOES STUFFED WITH CHEESE,
COATED IN PIG.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, WHERE HAS THIS BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
CUT OFF THE END.
TAKE OUT THE LITTLE CORE.
GIRL, YOU HAVE FAR TOO MUCH TIME
ON YOUR HANDS.
I KNOW. LOCAL ASIAGO CHEESE.
WRAP IT IN SAUSAGE.
PUT EGG IN THE BOWL.
OKAY.
SAUSAGE.
LOCAL PORK?
YEAH. COMBINE THAT.
AND THIS RECIPE
IS FROM?
PARTY IN MY HEAD.
THERE'S A PARTY
IN YOUR HEAD?
IS THAT WHAT I HEAR
GOING ON?
ALL THE TIME.
WE TAKE THE SAUSAGE
AND MAKE A LITTLE PATTY.
PUT THE TOMATO IN THE SAUSAGE
AND WRAP IT UP.
AND THEN FRY IT?
NO. FIRST WE'RE GONNA
BREAD IT.
WE'RE GONNA
BREAD THIS, ALSO?
YEAH, IN THE SAME--
THAT WE DID
WITH THE CHICKEN?
MM-HMM.
SAME DEAL,
JUST ADD THE SQUEAL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL GOBBLE
AND FULL THROTTLE.
TEQUILA-INFUSED
GARLIC BUTTER,
THEN DEEP-FRIED
IN JAGERMEISTER.
YUM.
OKAY.
OKAY, WE DEEP-FRY 'EM
FOR ABOUT FOUR TO FIVE MINUTES.
THEN WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
THE TOMATO TZATZIKI,
WHICH IS THE SAUCE
FOR THE TOMATO BONBONS.
GOT IT.
SO WE START
WITH OUR HOMEMADE SALSA--
YELLOW ONION, ROMA TOMATOES,
FRESH JALAPEÑOS,
CILANTRO, FRESH LIME JUICE,
OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY.
COMBINE THAT.
PUT IT IN THE BOWL HERE.
SO A LITTLE, UH--
OKAY, SO THIS OUR
HOMEMADE RANCH DRESSING,
ENGLISH CUCUMBERS.
I'M A FAN
OF THE ENGLISH CUCUMBER.
THE OTHER CUCUMBER
JUST HAS TOO MUCH SEED
AND TOO TOUGH A SKIN.
YEAH. PUT SOME OF THE TZATZIKI
INTO THE CHINESE SOUP SPOON.
HERE ARE THE BONBONS
FRESH OUT OF THE FRYER.
WOW.
GARNISH WITH A TOMATO--
AN HOMAGE TO THE TOMATO INSIDE.
AHH.
A LITTLE PARSLEY.
SO THERE IT IS--SMOLDERING
NUGGETS OF CHEESE AND PIG.
(crunch) MMM.
WOW, THAT'S NICE.
A LITTLE BIT OF CHEESE
LEAKS OUT OF THE TOMATO,
BUT IT'S ENCASED
IN THE PORK,
WHICH IS ENCASED
BY THE ASIAGO BREADING.
IT'S A CROSS BETWEEN A MEATBALL,
A DUMPLING, AND A SCOTTISH EGG.
PUT A LITTLE, CLASSY SPIN ON
WITH THIS TZATZIKI SALSA.
BUT THE REALITY OF IT IS
IT'S JUST GOOD, OLD, DOWN-HOME,
CRUNCHY, FRIED GREATNESS.
I'D EAT THAT
OFF A DIRTY PLATE.
YOUR TOMATO BONBONS.
FRESH HERBS,
IT'S ALWAYS CRISP.
(crunch) MMM.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
BUT REALLY SAVORY.
PLATING TOMATO BONBONS.
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
SALMON AND SCALLOPS.
THE BEST THING
ABOUT THIS PLACE
IS VALERIE'S
WONDERFUL CREATIONS.
BURGER UP!
I'VE HAD EVERYTHING ON THE MENU.
EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
SHREDDED BEEF SANDWICH.
GREAT FLAVOR, AND IT COMES FROM
THE HEART. THAT GOES A LONG WAY.
TO ZEST!
ALL RIGHT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP.
IF YOU WANT TO GET THE RECIPES
FROM THIS SHOW,
GO TO foodnetwork.com,
AND I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
OUT.
OW!
I GOT IT.
LET'S GET ALL THOSE JUICES
AND... GOOD.
OKAY.
(imitates engine revving)