HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WAKE UP AT HOME!
OLD FAVES...
LOOK AT THIS.
MEET NEW CRAVES...
THE ANTICIPATION
IS KILLING ME.
IN SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA...
THIS FEELS VERY
LONG ISLAND TO ME.
THE PASTRAMI JOINT...
BASICS, BABY. WHAT,
ARE YOU KIDDING ME HERE?
THIS IS PRETTY RIGHTEOUS.
SERVING UP A TWIST
ON THE TRADITIONAL...
OH, LOOK AT THE
CRUNCH-ITATION.
YEP.
WITH A SIDE ORDER OF ROAST.
HUNTER, YOU EVER WATCH
YOUR OLD MAN DYE HIS HAIR?
(laughter)
IN CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA...
ALL RIGHT, HERE'S
THE JERK CHICKEN SANDWICH.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN...
A RETRO GAS STATION...
LOOK AT THE BOUNTY
OF THE COUNTY.
TURNED INTO
AN ISLAND EATERY.
WHAT'D HE SAY?
IN VANCOUVER, B.C...
MEAT AND BREAD--
WHAT A CONCEPT.
A 4-SANDWICH STOP...
WHO WOULD HAVE THUNK?
MAKING EACH ONE COUNT.
THAT'S A SKIN MOISTURIZER
IN FLAVOR TOWN,
RUNNING DOWN YOUR ARM.
DELICIOUS PORK LOTION.
YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D,"
I'M ALWAYS LOOKING
FOR A LITTLE SURPRISE.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE, LIKE,
THE BOMB TACO ON THE EAST COAST,
OR MAYBE SOME RIGHTEOUS PASTRAMI
ON THE WEST COAST,
SO WHEN A BRO CALLS ME UP,
HE SAYS,
"MAN, YOU GOTTA MEET ME
IN SANTA BARBARA,
'CAUSE I GOT THIS JOINT
THAT IS ROCKIN' THE PASTRAMI,"
WELL, YOU KNOW I JUST
GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
(horn honks)
DAD, COME ON,
I'M STARVIN'.
HANG ON, SON,
WE'RE HERE.
THIS IS NORTON'S.
WHAT MAKES NORTON'S
SO COOL?
THE PASTRAMI.
IF YOU WANT THE BEST
PASTRAMI SANDWICH,
THIS IS THE PLACE TO GO.
PASTRAMI REUBEN UP.
THAT'S THE WORD FROM COUNTRY
ROCKER BRAD PAISLEY.
I'VE NEVER HAD BETTER PASTRAMI
THAN THIS PLACE.
CAN'T IMAGINE THERE'S
ANYTHING BETTER.
AND THE BRO WHO
TURNED ME ON TO THIS JOINT,
MY MAN DENNIS MILLER.
I SAW THE BLACK AWNING, IT SAID
I GOTTA GO TRY THE 'STRAMI HERE.
DID YOU JUST
CALL IT 'STRAMI?
'STRAMI.
'CAUSE I WANT TO JUST
BE ON THE IN.
EVERYBODY GOES SHORTHAND.
I SAID, I GOTTA GO
DIG THE 'STRAMI,
AND THIS FEELS VERY
LONG ISLAND TO ME.
THIS FOOD YOU GET
MOSTLY ON THE EAST COAST,
YOU KNOW,
THE NEW YORK-STYLE DELIS.
PASTRAMI REUBEN,
COMIN' UP.
BRING A LITTLE EAST COAST
TO THE WEST--
ALL PART OF THE MASTER PLAN
FOR OWNERS BILL KLEIN
AND TOM DOOLEY.
CAME HERE IN 2008,
ATE AT NORTON'S.
WHEN WE LEFT HERE,
WE THOUGHT, WHY DON'T WE GO
IN THE CENTURY 21 OFFICE
UP THE STREET HERE,
AND SEE WHAT'S AVAILABLE
HERE FOR RESTAURANTS.
WE ENDED UP BUYING IT.
AND THE LOCALS ARE DIGGIN'
THE NEW OWNERS.
I COME IN,
BILLY'S A SQUARE CAT,
WORKS HIS ASS OFF. I GOTTA
KISS THE RING HERE, MAN.
BILLY'S MY GUY.
HOW MANY POUNDS
OF PASTRAMI IN A WEEK?
MAYBE ABOUT 320.
320 POUNDS, REALLY?
SERVED UP SIX DIFFERENT WAYS.
BASICS, BABY. I DON'T
NEED ALL THE AUGMENTATION.
WHAT, ARE YOU KIDDING ME HERE?
YOU COME IN WITH
THE SPICE GIRLS?
I JUST WANT 'STRAMI ON A ROLL,
GIVE ME A LITTLE THOUSAND
ISLAND. THAT'S ALL I CARE ABOUT.
PASTRAMI DIP SANDWICH.
IT'S A GREAT WAY TO ENHANCE
THE SANDWICH EVEN FURTHER.
THE P.L.T.--PASTRAMI, LETTUCE,
TOMATO--CHANGE YOUR WORLD.
YOU CAN'T GET IT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKIN'
THE P.L.T.
THAT'S WHAT I WANT
IN MY FRIDGE.
LOOK AT THAT. WHOA, WHOA, WHOA--
IS THAT HOW MUCH GOES ON ONE?
MINIMUM OF 8 OUNCES,
'CAUSE IT'S DONE BY EYESIGHT,
AND THEN UP TO 10.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF MEAT.
YOU'RE MAKING
A PASTRAMI PATTY?
I AM.
WE'RE GONNA CRISP THIS UP,
TURN IT INTO A CRISPY PATTY
THAT SIMULATES
THE TEXTURE OF BACON.
VERY SIMILAR--
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
YEP. PUT SOME SOURDOUGH DOWN
ON THE GRILL AT THIS POINT.
THE SEASONING OF THE GRILL
WITH THE POUND OF BACON--
THAT HAPPENS
EVERY MORNING?
IT HAPPENS EVERY MORNING,
AND SOMETIMES MORE THAN ONCE.
WE GO THROUGH A LOT OF BACON
AS WELL AS PASTRAMI.
OH, LOOK AT THE
CRUNCH-ITATION.
YEP.
THAT'S A MONSTER.
BREAD GRILLED
REAL WELL,
SO IT CAN SUPPORT
THE MEAT.
YEAH, IF YOU DON'T HAVE
A NICE CRUST ON THAT,
YOU'LL WORK
RIGHT THROUGH IT.
AT THIS POINT, WE CAN
TAKE OUR BREAD OFF.
CHIPOTLE MAYONNAISE ON THE
BREAD. A GOOD AMOUNT ON THERE.
TOMATO FIRST. STAYS TO
THE BREAD. REAL FRESH ROMA.
LETTUCE ON TOP OF THAT. WHAT
EVERYBODY LIKES ABOUT A B.L.T.,
BUT WE CRANK IT UP
A NOTCH IN FLAVOR.
BLOWS A REGULAR B.L.T.
OUT OF THE WATER.
THE ANTICIPATION
IS KILLING ME.
WE'RE READY TO DO IT.
PUT IT RIGHT ON TOP.
THAT'S A RIDICULOUS
AMOUNT OF PASTRAMI.
CUT, IN THE BOAT.
ALL RIGHT.
LOOK AT THIS MONSTROSITY.
MMM. ME LIKEY.
WHAT CAN YOU NOT LOVE
ABOUT THIS?
NOW I DON'T HAVE TO HAVE
PASTRAMI AND BACON--
I'M WATCHING MY PETITE
DANCER'S FIGURE--
NOW I GET IT ALL TOGETHER,
AND ON THE BACK OF IT,
I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CHIPOTLE MAYO.
DUDE. YOU HAVE
LICENSE ON THAT.
KILLIN' IT.
MOM'S P.L.T.
HERE YOU GO.
THE PASTRAMI BASICALLY
TASTES LIKE BACON.
HUNTER, YOU EVER WATCH
YOUR OLD MAN DYE HIS HAIR?
(laughter)
WHAT'S THAT LIKE?
WHAT DO YOU GOT, LIKE,
EIGHT EARRINGS ON?
WHAT DO YOU--WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
I KNEW YOU WHEN
YOU WERE GUY.
REALLY, THEY HAVE GREAT
SANDWICHES HERE.
YOU SHOULD COME DOWN.
SO WHAT ELSE?
I HAVE A HOT DOG HERE
ONCE IN A WHILE.
BUT EVEN THE HOT DOG
TAKES YOU BACK TO 'STRAMI.
'STRAMI DOG,
COMIN' UP.
IT'S A HOT DOG AND PASTRAMI. TWO
OF MY FAVORITE THINGS TOGETHER.
THIS IS NORTON'S
PASTRAMI DOG.
SO, DOG DOWN.
THAT'S A 1/4-POUND DOG.
AGAIN THE PRESS.
DO YOU ONLY HAVE ONE PRESS?
WE HAVE A FEW, BUT THEY'RE
RESTING RIGHT NOW.
THEY HAVE THE DAY OFF.
REALLY? GOTTA
WORK 'EM THAT HARD?
AND THEN, UH, PASTRAMI.
LESSER PORTION, 'CAUSE
YOU GOT THE DOG ALREADY.
BUT YOU DO HEAT IT UP
ON THE FLAT TOP AGAIN?
YES, ABSOLUTELY,
'CAUSE PEOPLE WANT
THAT SLIGHT CRISP.
A LITTLE BIT
OF TEXTURE TO IT.
EXACTLY.
GOT IT.
GET THE BREAD,
JUST PUT IT ON THE GRILL,
JUST TO HEAT IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
ROLL THE ROLL OVER,
NICE KRAUT ON THERE.
LIKE THE KRAUT TO BE
MIXED IN WITH THE MEAT.
SWISS GOES ON TOP,
THE DOG GOES IN THE BUN.
THE MEAT'S GONNA GO
RIGHT ON TOP.
(whistles)
NORTON'S PASTRAMI DOG.
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
IT ALMOST FEELS LIKE SACRILEGE
TO EAT THIS WITH A FORK.
JUST PICK IT UP.
LOOK AT THIS.
MMM. THAT'S MEAT
ON MEAT.
(mumbling)
THE BUN AND THE CHEESE--
KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
GOT IT.
HE SPEAKS
PASTRAMI-ANESE.
PROBABLY WROTE THE DICTIONARY.
FUNKY JOINT, GREAT STUFF.
THANKS.
'STRAMI DOG UP.
A MOUND OF HAPPINESS,
IS WHAT IT IS.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT'S WHAT
A MOUND OF HAPPINESS WAS.
NOW YOU'RE IN THE KNOW.
THIS IS STILL THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GET BETTER THAN THIS.
EVERY TIME I SEE YOU
ON THE SHOW,
I SEE A CAT WHO CAME THERE
WITH HIS DAD,
AND 40 YEARS LATER,
HE'S BRINGING HIS KID.
I DIG THAT. IT'S LIKE
PACKER SEASON TICKETS,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THAT'S WHAT NORTON'S IS LIKE.
GET IN THIS!
LET ME SEE
THIS PUPPY.
I DIDN'T EVEN THINK
IT ACTUALLY EXISTED.
DENNIS MILLER
JUST TOOK THE '68.
SEE YA.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED OFF
TO VANCOUVER, B.C...
ONE PORK.
THIS IS GANGSTER,
CULINARY GANGSTER.
WHERE A SMALL MENU...
THEY ONLY MAKE FOUR KINDS
OF SANDWICHES A DAY.
MEANS MONSTER FLAVOR.
I CAN'T EVEN
REMEMBER MY NAME.
SO I'M HERE IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT I HEAR YOU CAN VISIT
365 DAYS OUT OF THE YEAR
AND EAT A DIFFERENT
SANDWICH EVERY DAY.
THE KICKER IS,
THEY ONLY MAKE
FOUR KINDS
OF SANDWICHES A DAY.
OH, THIS I GOTTA SEE.
WELCOME TO MEAT & BREAD.
PORK. GRILLED CHEESE.
ONE MEATBALL. ONE BEEF.
IT'S JUST STRAIGHT UP. IT'S
ALL ABOUT THE MEAT AND BREAD.
WHAT DID YOU THINK,
FIRST TIME YOU WALK IN,
AND THEY'VE GOT THIS BIG
ROUND-O-PORK
SITTING IN THE WINDOW?
THANK GOD.
THIS IS ONE OF A KIND.
ACTUALLY,
FOUR OF A KIND.
ONE FOR EACH SANDWICH
THEY'RE SELLING.
IT'S EASY MATH,
WHICH YOU KNOW I DIG.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE
TODAY, SIR?
WE HAVE PORK, BRAISED BEEF,
MEATBALL, OR GRILLED CHEESE?
IT'S A SIMPLE MENU, BUT IT'S
JUST VERY WELL EXECUTED.
THANK YOU.
WHO CAME UP
WITH THE IDEA?
IT KIND OF EVOLVED FROM
SOMETHING VERY SIMPLE,
BUT, UH, CORD AND MYSELF
MET IN DUBLIN.
WE USED TO WORK IN A RESTAURANT
TOGETHER OVER THERE.
WE USED TO GO FOR SUNDAY
CARVERY, OR ROAST DINNER.
WE THOUGHT, LIKE, WOW, HOW ABOUT
PUTTING THAT INTO A SANDWICH?
WHO WOULD'VE THUNK?
MEAT AND BREAD--
WHAT A CONCEPT.
ONE PORK.
ONE BEEF, ONE MEATBALL.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE
TO GET A SANDWICH, PERIOD.
THAT'S THE KIND OF RESPONSE
THAT HAS GOTTEN
OWNERS CORD JARVIE
AND FRANKIE HARRINGTON
SELLING OVER
300 SANDWICHES A DAY...
FANTASTIC.
WITH CHEF JOE SARTOR
DOING THE HEAVY LIFTING,
ESPECIALLY WITH
THIS BIG BOY.
THE PORCHETTA
IS JUST AMAZING.
IT'S A PERFECT
BALANCE OF THE FAT,
AND THE CRACKLING
IS SALTY AND CRUNCHY.
AS A SANDWICH GOES, THIS IS BIG
AND IT'S BOLD, AND I LIKE THAT.
AND THE SALSA VERDE
THAT THEY DO IS AWESOME.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SALSA VERDE
FOR THE PORCHETTA.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE PARSLEY.
TOASTED FENNEL, GROUND.
TOASTED CORIANDER,
ALSO GROUND.
GREAT.
CHILI FLAKES,
A LITTLE BIT OF KOSHER SALT.
OKAY.
FRESH GARLIC,
THE ZEST OF TWO LEMONS.
A BIT OF CANOLA OIL
IN THERE,
AND START
THE BLENDING PROCESS.
FINISH IT OFF WITH A BIT
OF FRESH LEMON JUICE.
HOW'S THAT SERVED
WITH THE PORCHETTA?
THAT'S GONNA GO ON TOP
OF THE PORK
AFTER IT'S SLICED
ONTO THE BREAD ROLL.
WHAT ARE WE ONTO NEXT?
ALL RIGHT, SO HERE WE'RE
GONNA MAKE THE SALT RUB
THAT GOES ON THE PORK
BEFORE WE ROAST IT.
WHICH IS GONNA GIVE
YOU THE CHANCE TO GET
THAT REALLY NICE CRUST ON IT,
AND REALLY GET THAT
NICE, TENDER,
PULL-APART MEAT.
YEAH, SO WE'RE
GONNA TAKE THE SALT,
AND WE HAVE PRETTY MUCH
THE SAME INGREDIENTS
THAT WERE IN
THE SALSA VERDE.
OKAY.
SOME CHILI FLAKE,
TOASTED FENNEL SEED,
SOME WHOLE DRIED ROSEMARY,
TOASTED.
ROSEMARY, MAN--
YOU GET THAT--ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT'S CONCENTRATED--
IT BECOMES
QUITE PUNGENT.
I MEAN, IT'S REALLY,
REALLY STRONG.
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLACK PEPPER.
AND THEN MORE LEMON ZEST...
MORE LEMON ZEST.
THAN ONE SHOULD HUMANLY
MAKE IN A DAY.
YES.
AND WHY THE LEMON ZEST?
PERMEATE THAT LEMON SCENT
THROUGHOUT THE PORK.
IT'S ALL LOCAL PORK,
HORMONE-FREE,
BEST PORK WE CAN BUY.
THIS IS NOT TYPICALLY
THE WAY IT'S BUTCHERED.
THEY HAVE IT SPECIALLY CUT
FOR THEM.
THERE'S BONES THAT ARE
TYPICALLY RUNNING INSIDE,
BUT TO HAVE IT ALL CONNECTED
IS JUST FANTASTIC.
THIS IS GANGSTER,
CULINARY GANGSTER.
SO WE'VE GOT OUR SALT RUB.
JUST GOING TO SEASON
THE WHOLE LOIN OF THE PORK,
AS WELL AS THE BELLY.
WE GENERALLY DO THIS
12 HOURS BEFORE WE ROAST IT.
OKAY.
AND THEN, UH, WE JUST HAVE,
UH, SOME CHOPPED HERBS HERE--
SOME PARSLEY, ROSEMARY,
FENNEL TOPS. WE SAVE THE TOPS.
GOT ALL OUR FLAVOR IN THERE,
JUST GONNA ROLL IT UP.
YOU NEED TO REALLY LEAVE
THAT EXTERIOR SKIN
FOR THE OUTSIDE TO CRISP UP
LIKE, UH, PORK CRACKLINGS.
YOU WANT TO MAXIMIZE
ALL THAT CRACKLING.
CRACKLING MAXIMIZATION--
SOMETHING YOU DON'T
HEAR EVERY DAY.
GIVE IT A QUICK TIE
SO IT COOKS EVENLY.
DO ANYTHING ELSE
TO IT?
WELL, WE'RE GONNA RUB IT
WITH OIL, OF COURSE.
YOU GOTTA RUB IT DOWN.
WE ARE HERE
AT THE MEAT & BREAD SPA.
AND THEN AGAIN WITH
THE SALT RUB ON THE OUTSIDE,
JUST TO HELP, UH,
CRISP UP THAT SKIN,
DRAW OUT ALL THE MOISTURE.
GONNA START THIS OFF
NICE AND SLOW,
ROASTING IT AT ABOUT 275 DEGREES
FOR AN HOUR AND A HALF,
GET IT ALL UP TO TEMPERATURE,
AND THEN FOR
THE LAST 35 MINUTES,
WE'RE GONNA BLAST IT.
SKIN WILL PUFF UP NICE.
LOOK AT THE CRACKLING
ON TOP.
ALL YOU REALLY NEED TO DO IS
JUST GO INTO
THE BACON FAT BUSINESS.
OKAY, LOOK AT ALL THAT
JUICE COMING OUT.
WOW, YOU DO GO THIN.
YEAH, WE TRY TO GET IT
NICE AND THIN.
THEN YOU'RE JUST GONNA
GIVE IT A LITTLE EXTRA CHOP,
JUST IN CASE.
SO YOU GET A LITTLE
BIT OF THE BELLY,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE LOIN
IN EVERY BITE.
ALL MIXED TOGETHER.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE EXCESS CRACKLING. MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT MORE FOR YOU.
FRESHLY BAKED
CIABATTA ROLL,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA PUT A BIT
OF THAT SALSA VERDE
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
I CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER
MY NAME.
IT IS SO JUICY
AND SO TENDER
AND FLAVORFUL
AND BALANCED.
NOT TOO MUCH ON
THE HERBACEOUSNESS
WITH ALL OF THAT ITALIAN
PARSLEY THAT WENT IN.
NOT TOO HEAVY ON THE GARLIC
OF THE SALSA VERDE.
THEN WHEN YOU DID THE RUB,
NOT TOO MUCH SALT,
NOT TOO MUCH ROSEMARY--ROSEMARY
CAN BE SO PREDOMINANT.
AND ENOUGH CIABATTA ROLL
TO HOLD IT TOGETHER.
BOOM.
KILLED IT.
ONE PORK.
IT'S AN IMPRESSIVE SANDWICH.
THEY HAD IT WITH THE MUSTARD.
GIVES IT A NICE LITTLE KICK.
HOW IS THAT?
DELICIOUS.
DO YOU SEE THIS RIGHT HERE?
THAT'S A SKIN MOISTURIZER
IN FLAVOR TOWN,
RUNNING DOWN YOUR ARM.
AND MY CHEEK.
AND YOUR CHEEK.
DELICIOUS PORK LOTION.
YEAH.
YOU JUST CAN'T GO WRONG.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA GET
SOMETHING GOOD THERE.
ROCKIN' IT.
I WILL BE BACK.
THANK YOU.
IF YOU BUILD IT, THEY WILL COME.
YOU HAVE BUILT IT.
UP NEXT...
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
WE'RE REFUELING IN
CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA...
I THINK I RODE THAT
PIG IN A PARADE.
WHERE SOUTHERN COMFORT TAKES
A VACAY DOWN IN THE CARIBBEAN.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW YOU EXPECT
ANYBODY THAT DOESN'T
HAVE A REMOVABLE JAW PIN
TO GET THIS
IN THEIR FACE HOLE.
SO HERE I AM IN
CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA,
ON THE PENINSULA, JUST A COUPLE
BLOCKS OFF THE MAIN DRAG
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT,
GET THIS, IT'S BEEN EVERYTHING
FROM A GAS STATION TO CAR LOT
AND A FISH MARKET,
BUT NOW IT'S HOME
TO A YOUNG 26-YEAR-OLD CHEF
WHO'S TOTALLY
RENOVATED THE JOINT
AND IS DOING HIS SPIN
ON AN ALL-AMERICAN MENU
WITH A LITTLE CARIBBEAN TWIST.
THIS IS FUEL CHARLESTON.
CHORIZO BURGER,
SIDE OF BLACK BEANS.
THEY ARE VERY PASSIONATE
ABOUT THE FOOD.
SHRIMP TACO.
HAS A REAL FRESH
TASTE TO IT.
BUFFALO BURGER,
SIDE OF RICE.
(woman) THEY'VE KEPT ALL
THE DETAILS OF THE GAS STATION,
WHICH MAKES IT A NICE
ECLECTIC PLACE.
SO WHAT MAKES
THE FOOD SO GOOD?
IT'S LIKE SOUTHERN
MEETS CARIBBEAN.
AND THE DUDE BRINGING
CARIBBEAN DOWN HOME
IS CHEF JUSTIN BROOME...
BLACK BEAN BURGER.
ORDER UP.
WHO TURNED A GAS STATION
INTO AN ISLAND EATERY IN '07.
CARIBBEAN, REALLY? WHERE'S
THE CARIBBEAN SIDE OF YOU?
TRAVELING THE CARIBBEAN,
UH, WHEN I WAS YOUNGER,
AND, UH, FILLING A NICHE
IN CHARLESTON.
VEGGIE NACHOS UP.
HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE CARIBBEAN
FOODS TO SOMEBODY?
I'D SAY FRESH,
AND BECAUSE OF THE CARIBBEAN
AND YOUR RESOURCES BEING
VERY LIMITED, YOU HAVE
TO REALLY TAKE WHAT YOU HAVE.
A LOT OF THAT IN SOUTHERN
COOKING, OR IN THIS AREA?
I THINK IT'S, UH,
CARIBBEAN-ESQUE, IF YOU WILL.
CARIBBEAN-ESQUE.
YEA.
SPIN, FLARE,
AND -ESQUE.
SHELLS UP.
HOWEVER YOU WANT
TO SAY IT,
THIS CAT'S BLENDED SOUTHERN
COOKING WITH TROPICAL FLAVORS.
PORK TACOS, BLACK BEANS,
ORDER UP.
THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE.
THIS IS A PORK TACO.
IT'S, LIKE, SOUTHERN
MEETS CARIBBEAN.
PORK TACOS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
HOUSE-MADE, UH,
CHILI AIOLI
FOR THE BRAISED PORK TACOS.
GOT OUR MAYO HERE.
ROASTED POBLANOS
AND JALAPEÑOS.
SEE THAT.
FRESH-CHOPPED CILANTRO,
A LITTLE MINT,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
A LITTLE HEAT.
(whistles)
FRESH SQUEEZED LIME JUICE,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
YOU MIX THIS UP.
PULVERIZER 9,000.
LET IT CHILL, SERVE IT
WITH THE TACOS.
YEP.
NOW THAT IS SOMETHING
YOU DON'T OFTEN SEE--
THE WHOLE SHOULDER. BUT HERE,
DOWN IN SOUTH CAROLINA,
I GUESS YOU CAN
PROBABLY JUST STOP BY
THE LOCAL
CONVENIENCE STORE
AND FIND THAT RIGHT
OVER THERE BY THE MoonPies.
WHOLE PIG,
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
WHATEVER YOU NEED.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKIN'?
IT'S GONNA BE THE DRY RUB
FOR THE PORK.
CHILI POWDER HERE, SALT,
GARLIC POWDER, DRIED OREGANO,
DRIED THYME,
SMOKED BLACK PEPPERCORNS,
BLACK PEPPER,
RED CHILI FLAKES...
(whistles)
AND CAYENNE.
GIVE THIS A LITTLE
MIX HERE.
SEASONING, UH,
VERY LIBERALLY.
IT'S LIKE A SAND STORM.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
A LITTLE COLA.
GIVES YOU A LITTLE COLOR,
CARAMELIZES,
ALSO TENDERIZES AS WELL.
I'VE SEEN IT
CLEAN A PENNY.
THAT IT'LL DO. FINISH IT
WITH A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR
AS WELL.
THAT'LL BE A NICE BARK
ON THAT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
FLIPPING.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THAT THING.
I THINK I RODE THAT
PIG IN A PARADE.
SAME PROCESS.
OKAY, SO 350 DEGREES,
6 TO 7 HOURS
UNTIL IT'S PULL-APART
PORK TENDER.
EXACTLY.
SIX HOURS LATER...
PEEL IT AND REVEAL IT.
NICE. LOOK AT THAT,
JUST PULL-APART TENDER.
MMM. WON'T KICK
THAT OFF THE PLATE.
JUST START PULLING IT
AND BREAKING IT.
EXACTLY.
WARM THAT PORK BACK UP,
HIT IT A LITTLE BIT WITH THAT,
UH, HOUSE-MADE
BARBECUE SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
OUR TORTILLA SHELLS ON.
GOT, UH, THE CHILI AIOLI
WE MADE EARLIER.
UH, SWEET ONIONS.
A LITTLE BIT OF SLAW.
SOME JICAMA IN HERE,
A LITTLE GRANNY SMITH APPLE,
GREEN CABBAGE.
FINISHING UP WITH
A LITTLE CHIVE ON TOP.
LIME.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW YOU EXPECT
ANYBODY THAT DOESN'T
HAVE A REMOVABLE JAW PIN
TO GET THIS
IN THEIR FACE HOLE.
PORK'S COOKED THOROUGHLY,
SHRED-TENDER. SLAW'S DYNAMITE.
SWEETNESS OF
THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
REINTRODUCING SOME
OF THE JUS
THAT WAS GENERATED
FROM COOKING THE PORK,
A LITTLE BARBECUE
SAUCE IN IT.
I THINK THE LITTLE ACID THERE
FROM THE LIME WAS NECESSARY.
BRINGS IT ALL TOGETHER.
MM-HMM.
EVERYBODY PLAYS NICE.
GREAT JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
BRAISED PORK TACOS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE PORK IS VERY TENDER,
IT HAS JUST ENOUGH SPICE,
AND THE AIOLI SAUCE GIVES IT
A CITRUSY TASTE.
BRO, YOU'RE A LITTLE SKINNY
AND A LITTLE YOUNG
TO BE THE CHEF
OF SUCH A BIG JOINT.
JUST SO YOU
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING,
THAT'S NOT GONNA
STAY FOREVER.
THE SKINNINESS?
YEAH. I JUST
WANT YOU TO HAVE
A BEFORE AND AFTER.
WE'VE HAD THE TACO,
I'LL TAKE THE LATIN INFLUENCE.
WHEN DO WE GET
THE CARIBBEAN?
JERK CHICKEN SANDWICH.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE HANGING OUT AT FUEL
IN CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA.
WE'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
WELCOME BACK,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN...
WELCOME BACK TO FUEL
IN CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE CARIBBEAN FOOD
I'VE BEEN PROMISED. LOOK AT
THE BOUNTY OF THE COUNTY.
LET'S COUNT HOW MANY
INGREDIENTS WE HAVE
COMING TOGETHER FOR THIS DISH.
WHAT DISH IS IT?
JERK CHICKEN MARINADE.
ONE, TWO, THREE...
(voices speeding up)
36.
I DIDN'T EVEN
COUNT THE CHICKEN.
37 INGREDIENTS.
ALL RIGHT, GET STARTED.
DICED YELLOW ONION,
MINCED GARLIC.
MAKING LIKE A LITTLE
MOJO HERE.
MORE OR LESS.
FRESH ORANGE JUICE, COLA,
PAPRIKA.
PAPRIKA!
CAYENNE PEPPER,
RED CHILI FLAKES.
(whistles)
THYME, CHILI POWDER,
CUMIN,
CORIANDER, SERRANO.
CHOCOLATE, MARSHMALLOWS...
THERE'S NOTHING WE DIDN'T
PUT INTO THIS. THERE'S MORE?
KITCHEN SINK'S COMING.
CIN-NA-MON-A-MON-A-MON.
OREGANO, MACE.
A.K.A., THE OUTSIDE COVERING
OF THE NUTMEG SEED.
FRESH GROUND GINGER.
TURMERIC, NICE COLOR.
CARDAMOM, FRESH SAGE,
CILANTRO, BLACK PEPPER.
TRYING TO WRITE IT...
LIME ZEST.
WHAT'D HE SAY?
ORANGE ZEST,
SALT, APPLE JUICE,
LEMON JUICE, SOY SAUCE...
UH-HUH.
HABANEROS, DIJON MUSTARD.
PICTURE OF MY KID
FROM SCHOOL--RYDER.
JALAPEÑOS,
PINEAPPLE JUICE,
FRESH LIME JUICE,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
FINALLY, COCONUT MILK.
JEEZ. WAKE UP AT HOME!
HE'S DONE ADDING
THE INGREDIENTS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA BLEND.
PLEASE.
LOOKS LIKE A PUNCH BOWL
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
CHICKEN GOES IN.
GET THE BIRD.
MARINATES
FOR 48 HOURS.
GRILL THE JERK CHICKEN.
LET'S GET THE BUN ON.
THERE'S THE PINEAPPLE.
NICE CHAR. BUN.
BIRD READY?
BIRD IS READY.
STILL NICE AND JUICY.
FRESH GRILLED PINEAPPLE,
APPLEWOOD SMOKED BACON,
GREEN CHILI AIOLI WE MADE
A LITTLE BIT EARLIER.
DIG IT. AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THAT, HUH?
WHOA!
WORTH THE WAIT?
THAT HAS TREMENDOUS FLAVOR,
IN A NOT--
NOT SUPER SPICY.
I THINK PEOPLE GET THE WRONG
INTERPRETATION OF JERK.
EVERYTHING FROM
CINNAMON TO PEPPER
TO THE O.J. TO THE GARLIC,
AND THE GRILLED
PINEAPPLE ON THERE
PUTS A NICE LITTLE TOUCH
AS WELL, GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEETNESS OF THAT,
A LITTLE TANG.
I HAVEN'T BEEN
TO THE ISLANDS LIKE YOU,
BUT I WOULD HAVE TO IMAGINE
THIS IS WHAT IT TASTES LIKE.
I'M IMPRESSED.
NICE JOB.
ALL RIGHT, HERE'S
THE JERK CHICKEN SANDWICH.
YOU KNOW HOW MANY
INGREDIENTS GO IN THAT?
GUESS, BETWEEN 1 AND 100.
3.
3, REALLY? 36.
JUST IN CASE ANYBODY
WAS COUNTING. I WASN'T.
THEY BRING A LITTLE BIT OF
THE CARIBBEAN TO CHARLESTON.
FUN JOINT. LOVE IT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME,
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU KNOW WHAT? I THOUGHT
I WOULD JUST SHOW UP
TO THIS LUNCH COUNTER,
AND I WAS GONNA BE SAFE.
I REALLY MISSED IT
ON THAT ONE.