I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
READY FOR ACTION.
WE'RE ROCKIN' IT OUT
FAMILY STYLE...
THAT'S WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT.
IN PARK SLOPE, BROOKLYN...
BEAUTIFUL.
THE LATE-NIGHT SPOT...
BRANDADE.
WITH BROTHER ONE
BEHIND THE BAR
AND BROTHER TWO TEARING IT UP
IN THE KITCHEN.
CHUG, CHUG...
CHUG, CHUG, CHUG!
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA...
ORDER UP. FISH TACOS.
TWO BROS GOING
ISLAND STYLE...
WE GONNA BE ABLE TO FIT
THE FISH IN THERE?
WITH MY KIND
OF DRESS CODE.
I KNOW THAT THE RULE IS
SOMEBODY HAS TO WEAR
FLIP-FLOPS.
AND IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
A FATHER, SON,
AND DAUGHTER JOINT
HAND-PULLING NOODLES...
THIS IS THE BOMB DOT COM.
THAT GET ME
UP ON MY SOAPBOX.
IF THERE IS ONE TYPE OF FOOD
THAT I AM A COMPLETE JUNKIE FOR,
IT IS PAN FRIED DUMPLING.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
CAN I START?
YOU CAN START.
I'M DONE WITH THE CEREMONY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
WE'RE HERE
IN BROOKLYN, NEW YORK,
IN A REALLY COOL NEIGHBORHOOD
KNOWN AS PARK SLOPE,
AND IT'S JUST A FEW BLOCKS AWAY
FROM THE FAMOUS PROSPECT PARK,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE TWO BROTHERS
ARE ROCKIN' THE NEIGHBORHOOD
WITH CUSTOM-MADE COCKTAILS
AND HANDMADE FOOD.
THIS IS DeCOURSY'S SIDECAR.
I'VE BEEN COMING HERE SINCE
THE FIRST WEEK IT OPENED.
IT'S THE PERFECTION
OF THE KITCHEN...
PICK UP, CUBAN.
MEETS THE PERFECTION
OF THE BAR.
SO MEET THE DeCOURSY BROTHERS,
FIRST-TIME RESTAURANT OWNERS
DOING WHAT THEY DO BEST.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN THE BARTENDER
SIDE OF THE FAMILY...
ALWAYS.
AND YOU WERE
THE CHEF SIDE?
YES, SIR.
SO WHEN THEY OPENED
THIS JOINT IN 2007,
BART MANNED THE BAR...
GOT A CROWD GOING THAT
KNOW ABOUT THE COCKTAILS.
AND JOHN GOT COOKIN'.
CONSIDERED
FRENCH REDNECK.
WHICH I THINK--
FITS.
YEAH, IT FITS.
PORK BELLY WITH KIMCHI--
VERY FLAVORFUL.
FRIED CHICKEN IS FAMOUS.
FRIED CHICKEN UP.
AND THEN THERE'S
THE FRENCH CLASSIC...
BRANDADE.
A CREAMY APPETIZER
COMBINING WHIPPED POTATOES...
BRANDADE.
WITH, GET THIS,
SALTED COD.
THIS IS
A FRENCH PREPARATION.
MONSIEUR.
OKAY.
A LITTLE ESCABèCHE, A LITTLE
PICKLED RED ONION ON TOP--
GOD BLESS YOU.
ESCABèCHE.
SO HOW WE GETTING STARTED?
CUT THE BRANDADE
INTO SMALL CUBES,
AND THE DESALINATION
PROCESS.
IN COLD WATER,
BRING IT UP.
HOW MANY TIMES DO WE
CHANGE OUT THE WATER?
THREE.
NOW WE'VE GOT IT
DESALINATED...
YEAH, DEFINITELY.
BUT NOW WE'RE GONNA CUT IT
WITH SOME OTHER INGREDIENTS.
SALT COD IN,
POTATOES IN...
GARLIC IN.
GARLIC, GREAT.
WATER, MILK.
AND JUST LET THIS
COME UP SLOW?
GONNA LET IT COME UP SLOW.
SO THE POTATOES COOK.
AS SOON AS THOSE POTATOES
ARE COOKED, STRAIN IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
BACK IN THE POT.
YES, SIR.
NOW WE GO TO THE MIXER.
HIT IT.
OLIVE OIL IN THERE,
1/4 CUP OF HEAVY CREAM.
OKAY, SO JUST ENOUGH...
YEP.
TO BREAK THAT FISH UP,
BREAK THOSE POTATOES DOWN.
LOOK AT THAT.
HIT IT UP TOP
OF THE SALAMANDER,
GET A LITTLE CRUST,
GET A LITTLE GRATIN ON THERE.
GET A LITTLE WHAT?
GET A LITTLE GRAT-AN!
A LITTLE GRAT-AN ON THERE,
THAT'S RIGHT.
(whip cracks)
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU--
OOH, CRUSTY, CRUNCHY.
NOW WHAT ARE WE
STARTING ON?
ESCABèCHE.
YEAH!
RED ONION,
GO RIGHT IN THERE,
A LITTLE GARLIC,
ROSEMARY, CUMIN,
WE HIT IT
WITH THE RED VINEGAR.
THIS IS MY SECRET
INGREDIENT HERE.
REALLY?
BEET JUICE.
SO A LITTLE BEET JUICE IN THERE
BRINGS SOME BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
YEAH, NOT ENOUGH SO THAT YOU
CAN ACTUALLY TASTE ANY BEET.
AND, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I THINK WHAT YOU'VE JUST SEEN
IS HE JUST MADE
THE...
ESCABèCHE.
YEAH.
I'M GONNA HIT IT WITH A TINY BIT
OF VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF CHOPPED PARSLEY,
SOME FLAX TOAST POINTS.
FANTASTIC.
CHEERS, BROTHER.
CHEERS.
MMM. DUDE,
THAT IS REAL DEAL.
I HAVEN'T HAD IT TASTE THAT GOOD
SINCE I LIVED IN FRANCE.
MMM. GREAT FLAVOR,
A LOT OF DEPTH,
A BROAD RANGE OF FLAVOR
WITH THE VINEGAR AND THE SALT
AND THE CREAMINESS
OF THE POTATO.
DUDE, IT LOOKS
LIKE AN APPETIZER,
BUT THAT WILL EAT LIKE A MEAL
LIKE YOU'D NEVER BELIEVE.
THAT'S RIGHTEOUS, DUDE.
NICE.
PICK UP, BRANDADE.
ESCABèCHE.
IT'S GOT A REALLY
GOOD TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT SORT OF THAT CRISPY
TOP, AND IT'S REALLY RICH.
IT'S A LOCAL JOINT.
YEAH, THEY'RE OPEN
UNTIL 4:00.
THEY'RE OPEN
UNTIL 4:00 IN THE MORNING?
SERVE FOOD
TILL 4:00.
NO...
PLENTY OF TIME TO CHOW DOWN
ON JOHN'S FRENCH REDNECK TAKE
ON STEAKS...
IT'S A DELICIOUS
PIECE OF STEAK.
AND SANDWICHES.
MEDIUM CHEDDAR.
THE BURGER IS PHENOMENAL.
INCLUDING HIS TWIST
ON THIS SOUTH FLORIDA STAPLE.
PICK UP ON A CUBAN.
CUBAN SANDWICH.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
OUR DRY RUB FOR THE PORK BUTT
FOR THE CUBAN.
I LIKE THE FLAVOR
OF UNTOASTED AND TOASTED,
SO I DO A LITTLE BIT
OF HALF-AND-HALF.
(record needle scratches)
YEAH!
WE GOT THE FEW TOASTED,
A CUMIN, MIXED MUSTARD SEEDS,
RAW FENNEL,
GOT A LITTLE ALLSPICE,
WHOLE BLACK PEPPERCORN.
WHICH YOU DON'T
WANT TO OVERDO.
RIGHT. VERY EASY
TO GO OVER THE LINE.
AND SOME CORIANDER,
ALSO BAY LEAF.
YUM, YUM, YUM, YUM.
OH, YEAH.
NOW WE'RE TALKING.
THERE WE GO.
(whistles sharply) SMELLING LIKE
A SPICE MARKET BAHRAIN IN THERE.
WOW.
YEAH. GOOD STUFF.
DARK BROWN SUGAR,
KOSHER SALT THERE.
THANK YOU.
OUR FANTASTIC
SPICE BLEND HERE.
SO WE DRY-RUB
A PORK BUTT NEXT.
I JUST DOT IT
A FEW TIMES AROUND,
SO IT'S GONNA
SOAK IN THERE,
THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF LOVE.
WE'RE NOT SHY.
AND LET THIS MARINATE
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT FOUR HOURS. AFTER THIS,
WE GO TO A WET MARINADE.
OKAY.
CILANTRO AND GARLIC,
AND, UH, JUST
TO HELP IT GO ALONG,
I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF BEER IN THERE,
AND WE ADD LIME AND ORANGE
ZEST AND JUICE.
NOW WE'LL LET THIS GO
FOR 48 HOURS.
RIGHT.
THEN WE'LL PULL IT OUT,
GO TO THE OVEN, 325 FOR 2 HOURS.
IT'S DONE, IT'S COOKED.
YOU GONNA SLICE IT,
OR YOU GONNA PULL IT?
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT.
AND THEN THAT'S GONNA
GO TOGETHER WITH THE HAM.
WHICH HAS A WET
MARINADE ONLY.
A LITTLE BIT OF
DIJON MUSTARD, HONEY,
BROWN SUGAR, PINEAPPLE JUICE.
GET THAT IN THERE,
NOW DOWN WITH BEER.
WE'RE GONNA SAY...
CHUG, CHUG...
CHUG, CHUG, CHUG,
AND GOOD.
THERE YOU ARE.
SO NOW IN THE OVEN?
COVER IT WITH FOIL,
THROW IT IN THE OVEN.
ABOUT SIX TO EIGHT HOURS.
HAM'S DONE.
WE'VE GOT THE, UH,
PORK BUTT DONE,
TOASTED BREAD--
WE'RE READY.
"EDWARD SCISSORHAND," YOU CAN'T
PICK IT UP WITH YOUR HANDS?
THE PICKLE,
THE SWISS CHEESE,
AND I LIKE TO GET THAT
UNDER THE SALLY,
GONNA LET THAT CHEESE
GET ALL BUBBLY.
YOU WANT TO KEEP AN EYE
ON THAT, DON'T YOU,
SO IT DOESN'T, UH...
YOU GOT MY BACK.
SO IT DOESN'T BURN.
BEAUTIFUL.
WE ARE USING CIABATTA.
CUT IT ON A LONG BIAS.
LET ME TRY THIS.
MMM. THERE'S SO MUCH
FLAVOR GOING ON HERE
THE HAM IS RIGHTEOUS.
I DON'T CARE--
YOU SERVE THAT HAM ON A STICK,
HAM IN A CONE.
HAM-SICLE. THE NATURAL
JUICE OF THE PORK,
A LITTLE BIT
OF SWISS CHEESE.
THAT IS THE MOST
GOURMET CUBAN SANDWICH
I THINK I'VE EVER TRIED.
THEY OPEN UP THE CUBAN BORDERS,
YOU BETTER GET OVER THERE
AND HELP 'EM OUT WITH THIS ONE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE THE MAN.
PICK UP, CUBAN.
YEAH, THIS IS THE BEST PORK
SANDWICH I'VE EVER HAD.
WHEN I TRY TO TAKE
PEOPLE HERE, IT'S A PLACE
THAT THEY'VE ALREADY BEEN,
AND THEN WE BOTH ENJOY.
JOHN AND BART--
THIS IS THEIR LIFE.
WHEN YOU COME INTO IT,
THEY KINDA MAKE YOU
A PART OF THEIR LIFE.
MAKE A LITTLE MUSIC--WHAT'S UP
WITH YOU GUYS MAKIN' MUSIC?
YOU'RE SINGING ABOUT
THE ESCABèCHE,
AND HE'S--HE'S DOING
A LITTLE DANCE.
SHAKY, SHAKY.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO VANCOUVER, B.C...
LOOK AT THAT.
AWESOME.
FOR THE BEAUTY
THAT IS HAND-PULLED NOODLES
AND PAN FRIED DUMPLINGS.
MMM. MM-HMM.
MMM.
WHEN YOU'RE EATING SOMETHING
THIS GOOD,
YOU SPEAK THE SAME
LANGUAGE.
MM-HMM.
MMM.
♪♪
SO THERE'S ONE OF THE THINGS YOU
GOTTA KNOW ABOUT ME AS A CHEF,
AND THAT IS THAT
I LOVE ASIAN FOOD,
AND NOT JUST ANY ASIAN FOOD--
PRIMARILY, POT STICKERS
AND NOODLES,
SO WHEN I HEAR THERE'S
A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
IN VANCOUVER, CANADA, JUST
THREE HOURS NORTH OF SEATTLE,
WELL, I GOTTA TAKE TRIPLE "D"
INTERNATIONAL
TO CHECK OUT
THE PEACEFUL RESTAURANT.
PEACEFUL BEEF ROLL.
VERY FLAVORFUL,
VERY TASTY CHINESE FOOD.
THIS IS NOT
YOUR SWEET & SOUR PORK,
CHICKEN CHOW MEIN,
EGG ROLLS KIND OF A PLACE.
THEY HAVE
A LOT OF AUTHENTIC DISHES
FROM OTHER PARTS OF CHINA.
THERE'S NO PLACE THAT
HAS ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
'CAUSE NO OTHER PLACE
HAS CHARLIE HUANG...
SICHUAN THOUSAND CHICKEN.
WHOSE DAD
TAUGHT HIM TO COOK
BACK IN THE SHANXI
PROVINCE OF CHINA.
OH, I HOPE I DIDN'T
MESS THAT UP.
NOW HE'S GOT HIS OWN KIDS
IN ON THE ACT.
IT'S A FAMILY FOOD, REALLY,
FOR US.
AMELIA'S IN FRONT...
ENJOY YOUR
MU-SHU NOODLES.
AND EUGENE'S MAKING
THE HAND-PULLED NOODLES
IN THE BACK WITH DAD
FOR THIS NORTHERN CHINESE DISH.
CUMIN LAMB
STIR-FRIED NOODLES.
WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO MAKE?
NOODLE DOUGH.
FOR OUR STIR-FRIED
CUMIN LAMB NOODLES.
ARE WE GONNA...
(whistling)
LATER.
LATER, OKAY.
LET'S START WITH
THE NOODLE DOUGH.
TWO SCOOPS
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
ONE OF THE PASTRY FLOUR.
YEAH.
WHY TWO KINDS
OF FLOUR?
BECAUSE--TO MAKE IT
MORE STRONGER.
MORE GLUTEN?
YEAH.
THE GLUTEN'S KIND OF WHAT
GIVES IT THAT ELASTICITY.
COLD WATER.
OKAY. COLD WATER.
LYE WATER.
LYE WATER. WHY DO WE PUT
LYE WATER IN THERE?
THEN FLOUR GET INTO
WATER MORE STRONGER.
SO THE GLUTEN AND THE LYE WATER
WORK TOGETHER TO MAKE THE NOODLE
MORE--MORE ELASTICITY.
YEAH, YEAH.
OKAY. HOW LONG?
A COUPLE MINUTES.
OKAY. NOW?
READY.
LET'S GO.
I GOTTA DO THIS WITH YOU.
JUST A SECOND.
JUST WANT TO GET
A LITTLE BIT.
ENOUGH.
AND THAT'S LYE WATER?
YEAH, RIGHT.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR.
GO LIKE THIS, THEN FOLD.
IT'S VEGETABLE OIL.
THIS IS WHERE YOU PULL IT UP
AND YOU SPIN IT.
YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND--
IN MY WORLD OF COOKING,
THIS IS ONE OF THE ARTS
THAT I HAVE GOT TO LEARN.
OKAY, I'LL SHOW YOU.
LIKE THIS.
NOW SEE WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE
IS HE'S JUST CONTINUING
TO MAKE MORE
AND MORE STRANDS.
HE SPINS IT ONE WAY,
THEN HE SPINS IT THE OTHER WAY.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT YET,
BUT IT IS SEPARATING ITSELF
EACH TIME.
ALMOST READY.
IT IS ALMOST READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU THROW IT LIKE THIS,
THEN YOU GO, STRETCH.
STRETCH IT AGAIN.
THIS IS THE BOMB DOT COM.
LOOK AT THAT!
AWESOME.
OKAY, THAT--
NOW YOUR TURN.
OKAY, SO NOW WE TAKE 'EM
OVER TO BOILING WATER.
UNTIL INSIDE IS COOKED.
LOOK AT THAT.
ONE FELL SWOOP.
GREAT CHEW. PUTS IT
INTO THE WATER BATH,
STOPS THE COOKING PROCESS.
NOW HE'S GOT 'EM READY
TO GO TO START THE DISH.
OKAY, HOT WOK,
HOT OIL.
SLICED LAMB.
GONNA PULL THE MEAT OUT,
GO INTO THE STRAINER.
NOW WE GO WITH THE VEG.
RED PEPPER, GREEN PEPPER,
ONION, JALAPEÑO.
JALAPEÑO. GONNA BE SPICY.
TEASPOON OF CUMIN.
RED CHILI FLAKE.
SUGAR.
A LITTLE SALT.
BACK IN WITH THE VEG.
A LITTLE HOT WATER ON THE
NOODLES TO GET 'EM SEPARATED.
REAL HIGH HEAT RIGHT NOW.
NICE.
READY.
WHOO. LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. IT'S FRESH,
IT'S TENDER, IT'S SPICY.
MMM. THE NOODLES
WERE MADE BY HAND.
I CAN'T SHOVE 'EM
IN MY FACE FAST ENOUGH.
MMM. EVERYTHING ABOUT IT--
THE TEXTURES ARE GREAT,
THE PRESENTATION IS GREAT.
CHARLIE.
YES.
I'VE BEEN UP HERE
FOR THE OLYMPICS,
AND I'VE BEEN UP HERE
FOR SOME WEDDINGS,
BUT NOW THE REASON I WILL
COME BACK, WITHOUT QUESTION,
IS TO GET SOME OF THOSE NOODLES.
YOU'RE THE MAN. MMM.
I LOVE THE FACT THAT THEY'RE ALL
DIFFERENT SHAPES AND SIZES,
SO THEY PICK UP THE SAUCE
AND THE FLAVOR REALLY WELL.
ALL HANDMADE, AND ALL
MADE IN FRONT OF YOU.
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS I LIKE.
I LIKE OPEN KITCHENS.
EVEN THOUGH I COULD BARELY
SQUEEZE INTO THIS ONE,
CHARLIE'S STILL CRANKING OUT
OVER 120 DISHES,
INCLUDING ONE
OF MY ALL-TIME FAVES.
PAN FRIED DUMPLING.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
IF THERE'S ONE TYPE OF FOOD
THAT I AM A COMPLETE JUNKIE FOR,
IT IS ASIAN FOOD,
AND PARTICULARLY
THE PAN FRIED DUMPLING.
YEAH, THANK YOU.
CAN I START?
YOU CAN START.
I'M DONE WITH THE CEREMONY.
THIS IS THE GROUND PORK.
GROUND PORK.
THE PORK BUTT,
THOUGH, RIGHT?
YEAH.
THE SHOULDER.
YES. SALT.
VERY GENTLE.
SUGAR, SOY SAUCE--
LIGHT SOY SAUCE.
DARK.
DARK SOY SAUCE.
SOY SAUCE.
WHITE WINE. WHITE PEPPER.
WHITE PEPPER, GINGER,
CORIANDER.
SOME COLD WATER.
OKAY, SO WE MIX
THIS ALL TOGETHER.
THEN WE PUT A LITTLE
BOK CHOY.
A LITTLE BOK CHOY.
WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF SESAME OIL.
OKAY.
NOW WE START MAKING
THE DUMPLINGS?
SURE.
YOU FOLLOW ME, OKAY?
I'M GONNA TRY.
ROLL.
WHAT'S THIS SNAKE DANCE
YOU GOT GOIN'?
(humming)
YOUR LOOKS LIKE A COBRA.
MINE LOOKS LIKE
IT ATE A GOPHER.
PRETTY GOOD.
YEAH. OKAY.
HOLD LIKE THIS,
THEN TWIST.
OKAY.
AND THERE.
RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW...
OKAY.
MAY I SHOW YOU?
PLEASE!
HOLD ONE HAND, LIKE THIS.
OKAY.
PUSH DOWN,
YOU ROLL OUT ONE.
YEAH, YEAH.
ROLL TWO, ROLL THREE.
WAIT A SECOND--
MINE'S STUCK.
FINISH.
DOES THAT WORK?
ONE DUMPLING READY!
NOW WHAT?
NOW FOR THE FILLING
INTO THE DOUGH,
USE, UH, TWO FINGER.
I GO LIKE THIS...
YEP.
AND I PINCH IN.
IT'S GRAB AND PULL?
YEAH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S BETTER.
HUH?
YEAH.
WE GET THE PAN HOT.
THEN PUT THE DUMPLING.
MAKE SURE MINE MAKE IT
IN THE PARTY. OKAY.
ADD WATER.
NOW WE COVER IT,
AND WE STEAM IT.
SO NOW WE'RE COOKING THE PASTA,
SO WE PUT A LITTLE BROWN
ON THE BOTTOM, AND WHAT
DO WE SERVE IT WITH?
SOY SAUCE...
GARLIC?
SESAME OIL.
AND THE RICE WINE VINEGAR.
YEAH.
OKAY, READY? OH, OH, OH, OH.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, THEY LOOK GOOD.
LOOK AT THE BOTTOM. OH, HO HO.
MMM.
TENDER, BUT CRISPY.
THE MEAT,
NICE AND JUICY,
THEN YOU GET THE SOY SAUCE,
THE VINEGAR,
THE GARLIC
AND THE SESAME OIL.
OH, MY GOD.
OUTSTANDING.
I MAKE A LOT OF POT STICKERS,
BUT THIS IS THE BOMB.
MMM.
MM-HMM.
WHEN YOU'RE EATING
SOMETHING THIS GOOD,
YOU SPEAK
THE SAME LANGUAGE.
MM-HMM.
THESE ARE RIDICULOUS.
MMM.
MM-HMM.
CRISPY ON THE BOTTOM,
THEY'RE SOFT ON THE INSIDES.
IT'S A VERY SPECIAL PLACE.
A SPECIAL PLACE
WITH A UNIQUE DISH.
IF YOU'RE NEAR VANCOUVER,
YOU HAVE TO COME HERE
AND HAVE THE BEEF ROLLS.
THEN YOU KNOW
I GOTTA TRY 'EM.
BEST BEEF ROLL EVER.
♪♪
AT PEACEFUL RESTAURANT
IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
CHEF CHARLIE HUANG
IS CRANKIN' OUT
UNIQUE CHINESE FLAVOR...
REALLY AUTHENTIC.
EVERYTHING'S DIFFERENT.
AND HIS NUMBER ONE
IS ONE I'VE NEVER
HAD BEFORE...
(woman) PEACEFUL BEEF ROLL.
JUICY BEEF IN A FLAKY CRUST.
BEST SANDWICH EVER.
OKAY, NOW WHAT
ARE WE MAKIN'?
(Charlie) BEEF ROLL.
OKAY. WE'RE GONNA
COOK THE BEEF FIRST.
YEAH, WITH HOT WATER.
AND WHAT KIND OF BEEF
IS THAT?
BEEF SHANK.
BEEF SHANK, OKAY.
SO THE FOREARM OF THE BEEF.
LOTS OF FLAVOR, BUT TOUGH,
SO IT NEEDS TO BE COOKED DOWN.
THEN WE PUT THE--
STAR ANISE.
STAR ANISE, YEAH.
THAT'S A LOT
OF STAR ANISE.
THIS IS A--RIGHT.
RED HOT CHILI PEPPER,
CINNAMON.
BUT REAL CINNAMON.
CINNAMON. REAL CINNAMON.
BAY LEAF...
BAY LEAF, YEAH.
CLOVE.
LICORICE ROOT.
ALL THIS JUST FOR THE MEAT?
YEAH. YEAH.
FENNEL.
SO IT'S GONNA
HAVE AN ANISE FLAVOR
WITH THE FENNEL AND THE LICORICE
AND THE CLOVE.
BLACK, UH, CARDAMOM.
CARDAMOM. FLAVOR CITY.
GREEN ONION,
GINGER, SALT...
SUGAR.
THIS IS ROCK SUGAR.
ROCK SUGAR. WHAT A CRAZY FLAVOR
THIS IS GONNA HAVE.
MORE SALT.
SOY SAUCE,
REAL BLACK.
REGULAR SOY? LIGHT SOY.
LIGHT SOY SAUCE.
THE DARK SOY. REAL RICH FLAVOR
TO IT, OKAY.
COOKING WINE.
COOKING WINE, YEAH.
OKAY. OKAY, WHITE PEPPER. AND WE
LET THIS GO FOR FOUR HOURS
AND JUST SIMMER
WITH THE LID ON?
YEAH. YEAH. YES.
NEXT...
THEN POUR THE DOUGH.
OKAY.
SPREAD A LITTLE FLOUR.
LOOK AT YOU ROLLIN' OUT
THE DOUGH.
SHORTENING.
ANYTHING IN THE SHORTENING,
OR JUST SHORTENING?
SHORTENING AND THE FLOUR
AND THE SALT.
A LITTLE GREEN ONION.
GREEN ONION, YEAH.
ROLL IT.
THEN 3 OUNCES.
3 OUNCES.
YEAH, FOR THE INSIDE.
ROLL IT LIKE THIS.
THAT'S FOR YOU.
NICE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I DIDN'T GET YOU ANYTHING
THIS YEAR, BUT I'LL MAKE SURE
THAT I PUT YOU ON MY GIFT LIST
FOR NEXT YEAR. OH, I LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE MAKING SCALLION PANCAKES.
BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH.
HOW ARE WE GONNA
COOK THOSE?
PAN-FRY, OIL.
OHH! YOU GOT
THE MULTIPLE LAYERS.
YOU GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT SHORTENING IN THERE
SO YOU GET SOME FAT--
IT'S GONNA FRY UP.
IT'S GONNA BE LIKE A CROSS
BETWEEN INDIAN FRY BREAD
AND THE BOTTOM
OF THAT POT STICKER.
OKAY, YOU FLIP IT NOW?
YES.
OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
NO, NO, NO. PUT IT BACK.
NICE AND CRISPY. SEE THOSE
LAYERS I WAS TALKING ABOUT? MMM.
GREAT.
ALL RIGHT, THIS IS
THE HOISIN SAUCE WITH...
ROCK SUGAR.
OKAY.
AND SWEET BEAN SAUCE.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF GREEN ONION.
CHOPPED BEEF.
(whistles sharply) MMM.
YOU PICK UP THE STAR ANISE.
YOU GET A BIT OF THE LICORICE.
MMM. IT'S TENDER
AS CAN BE.
ROLL IT.
CHINESE BURRITO.
THEN YOU CUT.
READY.
(chuckles) MMM.
CRISPY, RIGHT?
(chuckles) YEAH.
CRISPY CRAZY!
THE MULTIPLE LAYERS,
THE CRUNCHINESS,
THE FLAKINESS.
THAT BEEF HAS GOT
CRAZY FLAVOR.
YOU GET THE FRESHNESS
OF THE GREEN ONION
ALL MIXED TOGETHER
WITH THE WILD HOISIN.
MMM. I'VE NEVER HAD THAT.
OUTSTANDING.
TABLE ONE, BEEF ROLL.
IT'S THE BEST
OF BOTH WORLDS, REALLY--
THE SALTY ELEMENT,
THE SWEET ELEMENT.
YOU GO FOR THE BEEF ROLLS,
AND IT JUST--
OH, THEY'RE CRISPY
AND BRING YOU IN.
THEY BRING YOU IN!
(man) IT'S THE BEST CHINESE FOOD
IN THE CITY.
SMALL LITTLE PLACE
IN A BIG CITY,
BUT WHEN YOU COME IN,
YOU MEET CHARLIE,
AND YOU SEE WHAT'S GOING ON
AND THE TIME HE'S TAKING,
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
OUTSTANDING.
COMING UP...
BARBECUE FISH TACOS.
WE'RE HEADED TO
A VIRGINIA BEACH HANGOUT...
MAKES YOU THINK OF THE BEACH.
THAT'S ALWAYS ROCKIN'
THE ISLAND TIME.
THAT'S HOW THEY DO IT
IN JAMAICA.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
SO HERE I AM
IN VIRGINIA BEACH, VIRGINIA,
AND I FIND OUT
THEY'VE GOT A JOINT
THAT'S NAMED RIGHT OUT OF
THE TRIPLE "D" DICTIONARY!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, THIS IS
FLIP FLOPS GRILL & CHILL.
TUNA WRAP IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
A CARIBBEAN FLAIR TO IT.
(man) BEER-BATTERED
MAHI SANDWICH.
THEY USE A LOT OF MANGO
AND FRESH FISH.
(man) ALL RIGHT, TUNA BURGERS
COMING OVER.
MAKES YOU THINK
OF THE BEACH.
DO YOU HAVE ANY FLIP-FLOPS ON?
YOU HAVE TENNIS SHOES ON.
YOU HAVE FLIP-FLOPS ON.
I KNOW THAT THE RULE IS
SOMEBODY HAS TO HAVE FLIP-FLOPS.
IF YOU DON'T, YOU PAY EXTRA.
JUST KIDDING.
BUT FOR OWNER KRIS THURBON,
GOING CASUAL'S NO JOKE...
(chuckles) AFTER 20 YEARS
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ.
SO IF I'M STAYING IN
THE BUSINESS ANY LONGER,
I'M GONNA DO IT FOR MYSELF--
A BIT MORE CHILL, LAID-BACK.
GOING WITH COASTAL CUISINE...
SHRIMP AND SCALLOP PENNE.
INSPIRED BY
AN ISLAND GETAWAY.
MY WIFE AND I WERE MARRIED
A COUPLE YEARS AGO.
WE WENT TO JAMAICA
FOR OUR HONEYMOON.
THAT'S WHERE I GOT THE MANGO,
THE PINEAPPLE,
AND REALLY TRIED TO INFUSE THAT
WITH THE FISH WE WERE DOING
AND GET A REAL
FRESH FLAVOR...
RECIPES HE'S KEEPING
IN THE FAMILY...
NEED A RUNNER--
ON THE FLY, PLEASE.
WITH HIS BROTHER
CHEF GARY HOOPER
BEHIND THE GRILL.
TELL ME
ABOUT JAMAICAN FOOD--
CARIBBEAN FOOD, I GUESS,
WOULD BE MORE LIKELY.
SWEET AND SPICY--
TROPICAL FRUIT
IN YOUR SAUCES,
BUT THEN YOUR SPICES
KIND OF COUNTERACT THE SWEET.
FISH TACO.
THANK YOU.
NUMBER ONE ITEM
ON THE MENU.
FISH TACOS.
HANDS DOWN?
HANDS DOWN.
(Gary) ORDER UP,
FISH TACOS.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
THE MANGO BARBECUE SAUCE
FOR THE MAHI FISH TACOS.
AND YOU KNOW I COME
FROM CALIFORNIA.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW YOUR MANGOS.
THIS ISN'T
A LEE PRESS ON TAN.
SO I'M GONNA PUT YOU UNDER
SOME PRETTY BIG SCRUTINY.
OKAY.
START WITH A LITTLE
VEGETABLE OIL, CHOPPED GARLIC,
CHOPPED JALAPEÑO,
CHIPOTLE PEPPERS,
AND ADOBO SAUCE.
DIG IT.
FRESH CHOPPED MANGO,
RED WINE VINEGAR.
SO NOW A LITTLE KETCHUP.
YEP.
PINCH OF SALT AND PEPPER,
BROWN SUGAR.
SO WE'LL LET THIS SIT
AND SIMMER DOWN FOR HOW LONG?
30, 45 MINUTES.
SMEAR IT ON
THE TACO SHELLS.
WE SERVE IT UP
WITH THE MAHI.
CORRECT.
GOT IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO FRESH MAHI.
YEP.
CAN'T BEAT THAT. HOW MANY OUNCES
GO FOR THE TACO?
UH, 4 OUNCES.
READY FOR ACTION.
YES, SIR.
FLATTOP.
A LITTLE S. AND P.
YEP.
SALT AND PEPPER.
ABOUT DONE HERE.
NOW TACO TIME.
FLOUR TORTILLAS.
WARM THEM UP
ON THE FLATTOP.
GOT A LITTLE CRISP LAYER
GOING ON. OUR MANGO BARBECUE.
WE'RE GONNA GO TO OUR SHREDDED
CHEDDAR MONTEREY JACK CHEESE,
SPICY COLESLAW,
OUR SALSA FRESCA.
ARE WE GONNA BE ABLE
TO FIT THE FISH IN THERE?
OH, YEAH.
AND LOAD THESE UP.
NEXT, A SLICE OF AVOCADO.
OKAY.
LIME CREMA.
THERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT,
TWO FULL-SIZED TACOS.
ALL RIGHT.
THE FLAVOR OF THE FISH RIGHT
OFF THE BAT IS NICE AND FRESH.
I MEAN,
THIS DEFINITELY HAS
MORE OF A CARIBBEAN FEEL TO IT
WITH THE SWEETNESS
OF THAT MANGO BARBECUE SAUCE
UNDERNEATH IT.
YOU GOT THE SOUR.
YOU GOT THE SWEET,
THE CRUNCH OF THAT SLAW.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
BARBECUE FISH TACOS.
(woman) BEST FISH TACOS
IN THE AREA.
WE HAVE A COUPLE OF DRINKS,
RELAX, WEAR OUR FLIP-FLOPS.
I USUALLY AM, TOO.
I PICKED THE WRONG DAY
NOT TO WEAR FLIP-FLOPS.
I KNOW. WE SAID THAT
RIGHT WHEN YOU WALKED IN.
BUT YOU THOUGHT FOR SURE
I'D WALK IN.
EXACTLY.
YEAH, NO, IT WAS
A LITTLE CHILLY OUTSIDE.
HEY, GUYS,
HOW WE DOING?
GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
I THINK WHAT'S REALLY GOING ON
HERE, YOU GUYS,
IS THAT THIS CAT'S
SPENT AS MUCH TIME
IN CORPORATE RESTAURANTS
AS I DID,
AND THERE IS NOTHING MORE
THAT YOU WANT TO DO
WHEN YOU'RE COMING OUT
OF CORPORATE RESTAURANTS
THAN LOSE THE TIE,
THROW ON THE FLIP-FLOPS.
ROCK THE FLIP-FLOPS.
SEE, THAT'S HOW YOU ROLL.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE RECIPES
FOR SOME OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKIN' FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(whispering) THIS IS WHERE I HIT
MYSELF IN THE FACE WITH IT.
(laughter)
SHH! DON'T LAUGH
AT HOME.
(laughter)