HEY, I'M GUY FIERI
ROLLING OUT WITH KID ROCK
ON A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(Guy and Bob) HEY, WE'RE BACK!
WE'RE CHECKING OUT SOME
OF KID'S HOMETOWN JOINTS...
MAKES ME WANT TO DANCE.
IN CLARKSTON, MICHIGAN.
THAT'S WHERE I'M FROM.
THE RESTORED CHURCH GIVING
PRAISE TO MAC AND CHEESE...
DID YOU JUST SHOVE THAT
IN YOUR MOUTH ALREADY?
YEAH.
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH TO STEAL.
ALMOST HAD SOME GANGSTER
ACTIVITY GOING ON HERE
OVER THE MAC & CHEESE.
A BLOCK AWAY, THE WOODSHOP.
SCRATCH MAKIN' AND SLOW SMOKI''
EVERYTHING...
ANYTHING NOT HOUSE-MADE
IN THIS JOINT?
NOTHING.
FROM BARBECUE...
(man) ALL RIGHT,
PORKER UP FOR TABLE 14.
(Guy) THAT'S PIG
ON PIG ON PIG.
TO ICE CREAM...
WHOO-HOO!
ARE YOU SEEING THAT?
AND IN WEBBERVILLE,
KID'S OWN HOME BREW...
I SAID, "MAN, I'M GONNA START
AN AMERICAN BEER COMPANY."
GETS THE ROCK STAR TREATMENT.
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT
I LIKE ABOUT THE BEER...
(man) OKAY.
EVERYTHING.
"A," IT'S FREE.
(laughing) IT'S FREE.
THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
BOB, THIS IS THE JOINT?
A CHURCH?
THIS IS THE CLARKSTON UNION
IN OUR LITTLE TOWN
OF CLARKSTON, MICHIGAN,
HOME OF THE MOST MACK-ING
MACKING-EST CHEESE.
OUT OF EVERYTHING
YOU COULD HAVE TAKEN ME TO,
YOU TAKE ME TO A CHURCH
THAT MAKES MAC AND CHEESE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
UH, BADASS BEER, MY BEER COMPANY
THAT'S HERE IN MICHIGAN,
WAS GIVEN BIRTH TO
IN THE BASEMENT HERE.
MAC AND CHEESE AND BEER
HANGING OUT WITH KID ROCK--
MY KIND OF JOINT.
MAC & CHEESE.
THE MACARONI & CHEESE
IS PRETTY MUCH
WHAT PUT CLARKSTON
ON THE MAP.
HERE YOU GO.
I LOVE THE ATMOSPHERE HERE. I
THINK THE CHURCH IS REALLY COOL.
AND FOR OWNER CURT CATALLO,
TURNING A CHURCH
INTO A COMFORT FOOD JOINT
WASN'T THAT BIG OF A STRETCH.
I HAPPENED TO GROW UP
IN THE OLD METHODIST CHURCH
THAT MY MOM AND DAD--
OH, TIME-OUT TIME--
YOU GREW UP IN A CHURCH?
YEAH, WE RESTORED A CHURCH
THAT THEY MADE INTO A HOME,
AND SO WHEN THIS
CAME UP FOR SALE,
IT MADE PERFECT SENSE
TO GRAB IT.
TAKING OLD CHURCHES
AND PLOPPING DOWN RESTAURANTS
THAT ARE KNOWN FOR
INCREDIBLE MAC AND CHEESE--
YOU HEAR IT EVERY DAY.
THAT'S WHY GUYS LIKE KID ROCK
COME IN AND STUFF.
I THINK IT'S LIKE, UH, THEY JUST
KNOW THAT WHAT WE DO IS REAL.
MY SON ACTUALLY WORKED HERE. HE
BUSSED TABLES HERE FOR A WHILE.
AND HE JUST WENT
OFF TO COLLEGE.
HE JUST WENT OFF
TO COLLEGE TODAY.
THE GUY DOESN'T LOOK OLD ENOUGH
TO HAVE A KID GOING TO COLLEGE.
FULL MAC.
I'VE HAD MAC AND CHEESE
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
WHAT MAKES THIS
MAC & CHEESE ROCK?
THE TOP.
THE CRUST IS AMAZING.
GO MAKE SOME
MAC & CHEESE?
YEAH, LET'S MAC IT UP.
AND, CHEF, WE'RE STARTING OFF
WITH PENNE RIGATE?
PENNE RIGATE.
RIGATE IS THE LITTLE RIDGES
THAT GOES AROUND
THE OUTSIDE OF THE PASTA.
IT HOLDS THE SAUCE REAL WELL,
SO I GUESS IT WOULD WORK GOOD
FOR--FOR MAC AND CHEESE,
BUT THAT'S NOT TYPICALLY WHAT
YOU FIND FOR MAC AND CHEESE.
WE DON'T DO ELBOWS.
NO ELBOW?
NO ELBOW.
DOING WRONG STUFF
IS FUN...
YEAH, LOOK--
LOOK WHO'S TALKING.
SOMETIMES.
WE'VE GOT
THE PASTA WORKING,
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
TO THE CREAM SAUCE.
FIRST WE ADD THE MILK.
ADD HEAVY WHIPPING CREAM.
SO HEAVY CREAM REALLY
ADDS THE RICHNESS TO IT.
ADDS THE RICHNESS, YEP.
OKAY.
INTO THE MILK
AND CREAM MIXTURE,
SEA SALT, FRESHLY GROUND BLACK
PEPPER, GROUND NUTMEG.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
BRING IT TO A SIMMER.
THIS MAC & CHEESE WAS
WRITTEN UP IN A BIG PAPER.
SOMEBODY STOLE THE RECIPE.
BORROWED THE RECIPE?
MAN, THIS WAS A BIG DEAL
IN CLARKSTON, MICHIGAN.
WE ALMOST HAD SOME GANGSTER
ACTIVITY GOING ON HERE
OVER THE MAC & CHEESE.
HOW IS THERE NOT
A SONG ABOUT THIS?
I WROTE PLENTY OF SONGS
ABOUT MACKING.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE START THE ROUX.
BUTTER, DICED ONIONS,
GARLIC PASTE.
PURéED GARLIC?
YES.
ALL RIGHT.
AND NOW THE FLOUR
TO BUILD THE ROUX.
YOUR ROUX'S MADE. MILK
AND THE CREAM IS SIMMERED.
THE NOODLES ARE FINISHED.
WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA ADD THE HOT MILK
MIXTURE TO THE ROUX,
AND WE'RE GONNA
LET IT THICKEN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME PARMESAN CHEESE.
ARE WE GONNA
MAKE BOB COOK AT ALL,
OR ARE WE JUST GONNA STAND HERE
AND LOOK GOOD AT THIS?
I THOUGHT YOU JUST TOOK
SOME NOODLES, CHEESE,
AND SOME PET MILK
AND THREW IT IN THE OVEN.
WHAT'S PET MILK?
IT'S LIKE
A CREAM SAUCE.
YEAH, IT'S, LIKE,
FOR YOUR DOG OR SOMETHING.
THAT'S PET MILK.
GUYS FROM CALIFORNIA,
WE DON'T KNOW STUFF LIKE THIS.
OKAY, SO NOW YOU CHILL IT
BEFORE YOU ADD IT TO THE PASTA,
AND THEN YOU ADD THE COLD PASTA
AND THE COLD CHEESE SAUCE,
YOU PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
MM-HMM.
THIS COULD FIX YOUR POTHOLE
PROBLEM IN DETROIT.
THAT IS TIGHT, MAN.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE SAUCE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT MORE CREAM
IN--MORE HALF-AND-HALF.
YOU ARE NOT SHORT ON
THE DAIRY ON THIS, MAN.
YOU'VE GOT TO DO IT BY HAND
SO YOU CAN FEEL THE LOVE.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S HOW
YOU KNOW IT'S DONE.
AND WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT INTO DISHES.
SOME PINCONNING CHEESE.
HAVE YOU HAD THIS PINCONNING
CHEESE? THIS SUPER CHEDDAR?
I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO CALL IT.
I WOULDN'T EVEN KNOW
HOW TO PRONOUNCE THAT.
IT COMES IN A WHEEL.
OH, GOOD STUFF, MAN.
YOU'VE GOT A LAYER
OF THAT CHEESE IN THERE,
TWO LAYERS OF THE MAC.
SHARP WHITE CHEDDAR.
NOW YOU GO WITH
A LITTLE PANKO ON TOP?
A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE TAKE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA BAKE IT OFF.
WHAT TEMP?
425, ABOUT 12 MINUTES.
AS YOU CLIP IT OPEN AND LET IT
STEAM A LITTLE BIT,
THEN YOU GET SOME OF THE CRUST,
GET A NOODLE IN THERE.
DO YOU SEE
THE STEAM COMING UP?
DID YOU JUST SHOVE THAT
IN YOUR MOUTH ALREADY?
YEAH.
DID YOU HEAR THAT KID ROCK
CANCELED SEVEN CONCERTS?
WELL, HE WAS HANGING OUT
WITH GUY FIERI.
HE ATE HOT MAC & CHEESE.
HE KICKED HIS TASTE BUDS.
MMM. YOU'VE GOT
THE CHEESE RIGHT IN THERE.
THEN YOU'VE GOT THE CREAM.
THEN YOU'VE GOT THE CRUNCH
ON TOP WITH THE WHITE CHEDDAR,
WHICH HAS GOT
SOME REAL NICE TANG TO IT.
THAT IS IN THE BOMB
MAC & CHEESE CATEGORY.
THE MOST MACKED
MAC & CHEESE.
(woman) YOUR MAC & CHEESE.
(woman) THANK YOU.
IT'S VERY RICH.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
CAN YOU EAT THE WHOLE THING
IN THE FIRST PLACE?
NO, I EAT HALF, AND THEN
I TAKE THE REST TO GO.
MEAT LOAF!
WHAT'S THE WHOLE
FOUNDATION OF FOOD?
WE DO, UH, BROAD-SHOULDERED
AMERICAN COMFORT FOOD
WITH A MEDITERRANEAN
TWIST,
AND WE LET THE FOOD
DO THE TALKING.
KID ROCK SAYS SOME OF
THE BEST HE'S EVER HAD.
THIS IS A MAN
WHO TRAVELS A LOT,
SO, LIKE, HIS WORD
OBVIOUSLY MEANS A LOT,
AND WE'RE FORTUNATE
THAT HE COMES IN.
IT IS REAL-DEAL.
JUST AN ALL-AMERICAN JOINT.
THAT'S WHY WE BUILT IT.
THANK YOU.
BEAUTIFUL.
♪♪
UP NEXT, WE AIN'T GOING FAR...
WE'RE NOT DRIVING?
TO GO WHOLE HOG.
"HOUSE GROUND PORK PATTY.
MI MAPLE BACON.
HOUSE MADE HOT LINK."
IT'S DRIPPING
ALL OVER MY HANDS,
AND I FEEL REALLY GOOD
ABOUT MYSELF RIGHT NOW.
HEY, CALIFORNIA BOY. THIS IS
CLARKSTON, MICHIGAN, MAN.
WE'RE WALKING
TO THE NEXT JOINT.
WE'RE NOT DRIVING?
NO, IT'S ONE BLOCK.
COME ON.
AW, KID, YOU'RE KILLING ME.
AW, COME ON. A LITTLE EXERCISE
WILL DO THE BODY GOOD.
(laughing)
I MEAN, LITERALLY
LESS THAN A BLOCK?
YEAH, RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS THE JOINT?
WHAT DO WE GOT?
YOU'VE GOT TWO
HALF CHICKENS.
TWO HALF CHICKENS.
ALL RIGHT,
RIB EYES ARE RESTING.
WHISKEY BAR IN HERE,
PIZZA KITCHEN,
BUT THE SMOKED MEATS
ARE WHAT WE'RE HERE FOR.
THAT'S THE BOMB?
THIS IS
THE UNION WOODSHOP.
CHECK THIS OUT.
HALF CHICKEN. ONION RINGS.
IT'S A WONDERFUL PLACE.
THIS IS COMFORT FOOD.
IT STARTED OUT
AS FINE DINING...
RIBS ARE DOING OKAY?
UNTIL OWNER ANN STEVENSON
AND PARTNER ERICH LINES
SWITCHED IT UP IN 2009...
ORDER IN.
PUTTING CHEF AARON COZADD
IN CHARGE.
SMOKY DOGS, JUICY LUCY,
TABLE 20. LET'S GO.
FINE DINING DIDN'T GO SO GREAT,
AND YOU SAID, "FORGET IT."
YEAH, WE SCRAPPED IT AND MADE
THE WHOLE THING RUSTIC, CASUAL.
TRULY JUST COMFORT FOOD.
ALL RIGHT, PORKER UP
FOR TABLE 14.
THIS IS AWESOME, BOB. SO WHAT DO
YOU WANT TO TRY OUT OF THIS?
THE PORKER.
"HOUSE GROUND PORK PATTY.
HOUSE MADE MI MAPLE BACON.
HOUSE MADE HOT LINK." ANYTHING
NOT HOUSE-MADE IN THIS JOINT?
NOTHING.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO
TALK TO THE CHEF.
AND GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
EVERYTHING'S
SCRATCH-MADE.
KIND OF TURNED BACK TO SOME
OF THE FORGOTTEN TECHNIQUES--
CHARCUTERIE, SAUSAGE MAKING,
CURING, SMOKING.
ALL MY MIDDLE NAME,
BY THE WAY.
EXACTLY.
IT'S GUY "CHARCUTERIE
SAUSAGE MAKING" FIERI.
THAT'S HOW I GOT
THIS PETITE DANCER'S FIGURE.
WELL, THIS IS
THE KID ROCK SPECIAL.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE THE SAUSAGE.
LET'S MAKE THE BACON.
I WANT TO SEE
WHERE IT STARTS.
I'LL DO YOU ONE BETTER--
I'LL SHOW YOU THE PIG.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH THE PIG?
THAT'S MY KIND OF DEAL.
ARE YOU IN FOR THIS?
OH, NO.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL
CATCH YOU IN A BIT.
NOT ONLY ARE YOU
SMOKING THE MEATS,
BUT YOU'RE BREAKING THIS DOWN
FROM WHOLE HOG.
THE CLOSER YOU ARE
TO YOUR RAW PRODUCT,
THE BETTER
YOUR FINISHED PRODUCT.
OH, YOU'RE PREACHING
TO THE CHOIR.
SO YOU TAKE
THE SHOULDER OFF,
AND THAT'LL GO FOR
MAKING THE SAUSAGE...
AND FOR THE ROUND PATTY.
FOR THE PATTY FOR THE POR--
FOR THE PORK PATTY.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THEN YOU
PULL THE BELLY HERE,
AND THAT'S WHERE
WE MAKE THE BACON.
EVEN SOMETIMES FOR
THE ADVENTUROUS CUSTOMERS,
HEADCHEESE.
NOBODY MAKES HEADCHEESE
ON TRIPLE "D."
LET'S BUTCHER THIS THING DOWN
AND MAKE SOME BACON.
SO WE'RE GONNA START WITH
BROWN SUGAR, KOSHER SALT,
CURING SALT OR PINK SALT,
LOCALLY PROCURED MAPLE SYRUP.
SO MIX THIS, RUB IT
ON THE PORK BELLY,
AND THEN HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA LET THIS CURE?
WE CURE IT
FOR SEVEN DAYS.
OKAY.
NOW WE'VE GOT THE PORK BUTT
AND WE'RE GONNA GRIND IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT! MY JOWLS JUST
TURNED ON. FLOODGATES. MMM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE UP OUR SPICE
FOR OUR HOT LINK.
KOSHER SALT, CAYENNE,
PINK SALT...
YEP.
CHILI FLAKES...
(whistles)
GARLIC, GRANULATED ONION,
THAT'S NUTMEG,
PAPRIKA, WHITE PEPPER.
DRY MUSTARD?
YES, SIR.
SEASONING SALT?
THAT'S A LITTLE
SPECIAL BLEND.
WHAT HE'S TRYING
TO SAY TO YOU IS,
"I'M NOT TELLING YOU
WHAT THAT IS."
SO WE GET OUR SPICE MIX, AND WE
ARE GONNA ADD A LITTLE WATER.
JUST GONNA
MIX THAT TOGETHER.
AND THEN WE'LL
GO AHEAD
AND THROW IT
IN THE SAUSAGE MAKER.
YES.
AWESOME. AND WE'VE GOT
SOME NATURAL CASING
THAT WE'RE GONNA
THREAD ON TO THIS.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF SAUSAGE
WILL YOU MAKE AT A TIME?
50-POUND BATCHES
AT LEAST TWICE A WEEK.
JUST GONNA
START 'EM OFF HERE.
THERE?
YEP.
NOW HOW MANY SAUSAGES
WILL YOU MAKE?
YOU'LL MAKE 100
WITH 50 POUNDS,
'CAUSE THEY'RE ABOUT
A 1/2 POUND APIECE?
YEP, ABSOLUTELY.
HANG 'EM ON THE ROD.
HANG 'EM ON THE ROD,
TAKE 'EM TO THE SMOKER.
AND HOW LONG WILL THEY SMOKE?
THEY SMOKE FOR
TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
A LOT OF WORK
AROUND THIS JOINT.
YEAH.
ARE WE READY?
WE'RE READY.
WE GOT OUR
FINISHED BACON.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'VE GOT OUR HOT LINKS.
BEAUTIFUL.
WE'LL GO INSIDE
AND CHOW.
FANTASTIC.
WE'VE GOT OUR HOUSE-MADE
MICHIGAN MAPLE SYRUP BACON.
OKAY.
THAT'S PIG CANDY
RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT.
GOOD BACON.
MAKES ME WANT TO DANCE.
I FEEL THE SAME WAY
HE DOES ABOUT IT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PORKER.
OKAY.
GOT OUR HOUSE GROUND
PORK PATTY.
SO GROUND PORK.
NOW WE'VE GOT
A HOUSE-MADE HOT LINK.
WE JUST SPLIT IT
DOWN THE MIDDLE.
OKAY.
MAKES IT NICE AND CRISP.
LOOK AT ALL THAT GREAT WHITE
FAT THAT YOU'RE GONNA GET.
YEAH.
THAT'S JUST
GONNA MELT.
THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE THESE
JOINTS THIS CLOSE TO YOUR HOUSE,
I DON'T KNOW WHY
YOU DON'T WEIGH 400 POUNDS,
UNLESS YOU HAVE, LIKE,
ON MAN SPANX OR SOMETHING.
YOU'VE--YOU'VE
SEEN THE SHOW.
YEAH, NO,
I HAVE SEEN THE SHOW.
THERE IS A--YEAH,
YOU SHOULD WEAR TRACK SHOES.
DOING THAT FOUR NIGHTS A WEEK
FOR TWO HOURS A NIGHT,
YOU KNOW, I CAN EAT
WHATEVER I WANT.
EVERYTHING IN MODERATION,
INCLUDING MODERATION.
WELL, WE'VE GOT
OUR COLD SMOKED CHEDDAR.
WE SMOKE THIS
IN-HOUSE, AS WELL.
OKAY.
JUST GONNA MELT THOSE UP
UNDER THE SALLY HERE.
THIS IS OUR
SOUTH CAROLINA MAYO.
IT'S MADE WITH OUR FROM-SCRATCH
SOUTH CAROLINA SAUCE.
YOU'VE GOT A VINEGAR-BASED
BARBECUE SAUCE
THAT YOU'RE MIXING WITH MAYO?
IS THAT WHAT IT IS?
IT'S A MUSTARD BASE.
MUSTARD BASE? OKAY.
YEAH. YEP.
THEN WE'VE GOT OUR HOUSE
PICKLED CHILIES HERE--
JALAPEÑO AND BANANA.
MAPLE BACON. WE'VE GOT
OUR PATTIES WITH OUR CHEESE.
IS THIS IN
THE MODERATION FACTOR?
OH, IT IS FOR ME.
SPLIT HOT LINK.
THAT LOOKS OFFICIAL.
HAND-CUT FRIES.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
THAT AIN'T NO JOKE.
I WANT YOU TO GIVE ME
YOUR CULINARY BREAKDOWN
ABOUT WHAT
YOU'RE TASTING.
THIS TASTES GOOD WITH THE SAUCE
AND THE SAUSAGE LINK,
AND THAT BIG PATTY
IN THE MIDDLE TASTES GOOD.
THE BACON SETS IT OFF.
IT'S DRIPPING
ALL OVER MY HANDS,
AND I FEEL REALLY GOOD
ABOUT MYSELF RIGHT NOW.
I THINK WE GOT
A FOOD DESCRIPTION
AND A SELF-HELP MEETING
KIND OF MIXED UP IN THERE,
BUT I DIG THE WAY
YOU'RE ROLLING.
HAD YOU DONE A RIFF ON THIS,
I WOULD HAVE SERIOUSLY LEFT,
GIVEN YOU THE CAR KEYS.
THE BUN IS PERFECT BECAUSE IT
WORKS AS A VESSEL TO GET IT IN.
THE LINK HAS GOT
SOME NICE HEAT TO IT
AND FANTASTIC TEXTURE.
THE PORK PATTY--YOU'VE GOT
THIS UNCTUOUS FLAVOR,
THIS JUICINESS
COMING FROM THE PORK.
WHAT REALLY SETS IT OFF
IS THAT CAROLINA MUSTARD
AND THE VINEGAR
FROM THE PICKLES,
'CAUSE YOU'VE GOT
THE SWEETNESS
COMING OUT OF THE MAPLE
FROM THE BACON.
THIS MAY BE 3-WAY PIG,
BUT A LOT OF COMPLEXITY
TO IT, MAN.
IT'S ROCK STAR
DELIVERING ROCK STAR.
I'VE GOT MY NAME RIDING
ON THIS, TOO, SO...
YOU'RE THE MAN.
I'VE GOT TO GO PACK, MAN.
MEET BACK UP WITH YOU, WE'LL GET
A COLD BEVERAGE OR TWO.
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
LET'S GO, CHEF.
THANKS A LOT.
THANKS, BOBBY.
(laughing)
UP NEXT...
ICE CREAM WITH WHAT?
A SMOKIN' DESSERT...
FREAKY.
WITH A ROCK 'N' ROLL FINISH.
WHAT, ARE WE HAVING
A RAVE PARTY DOWN HERE?
I GET IT ALL THE TIME.
FRIENDS HIT ME UP AND SAY,
"GUY, MAN, YOU'VE GOT
TO CHECK OUT THIS JOINT."
KID ROCK'S A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
THE CAT INVITES ME
UP TO THE DETROIT AREA,
HOOKS ME UP WITH HIS MOST
RIGHTEOUS TRIPLE "D" SPOTS,
AND COMES ALONG FOR THE RIDE.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE ROLLING
AT THE UNION WOODSHOP
IN DOWNTOWN CLARKSTON.
HERE YOU ARE,
HOMETOWN BOY, DOING GOOD.
THIS IS WHERE YOU HANG OUT
WHEN YOU COME HOME
WHEN YOU'RE OFF THE ROAD FROM
TOURING AND DOING ALL THAT.
THIS IS WHERE I'M FROM,
SO I TRY TO GIVE BACK
AND HELP PEOPLE OUT.
THEY ARE REALLY GREAT
MOM-AND-POP-OWNED RESTAURANTS,
YOU KNOW, BY GOOD PEOPLE
WHO ARE WORKING HARD
AND MAKING GREAT FOOD.
WORKING HARD TO SCRATCH-MAKE
AND SMOKE EVERYTHING
FROM THE MEAT TO THE CHEESE...
AND CHEF AARON COZADD
EVEN FIGURED OUT A WAY
TO PUT SMOKE INTO THE SWEETS.
MAPLE BOURBON SUNDAE'S
UP, GUYS.
ICE CREAM WITH WHAT?
WITH, UH, PEANUTS...
BOURBON.
AND BOURBON.
YEAH, I LIKE HOW HE DIDN'T
TELL ME THE BOURBON.
HE'S LIKE, "YEAH,
PEANUTS, AND--"
I WAS TRYING TO KEEP IT
A LITTLE MORE LOW-KEY.
YEAH, NO.
VERY--VERY LOW-KEY.
THIS IS LIQUID NITROGEN ICE
CREAM. CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
LIQUID NITROGEN
ICE CREAM?
YEAH, I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY
DO IT, BUT IT'S AWFULLY GOOD.
WE'VE GOT OUR LIQUID
NITROGEN--FREAKY--
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE ICE
CREAM IN THE MIXING BOWL
IN 60 SECONDS.
YES.
OKAY. DO I GET TO WEAR, LIKE,
A SUIT OR A HELMET OR ANYTHING?
UH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I JUST STAND--
I JUST STAND BACK
A LITTLE BIT.
BECAUSE ONE LITTLE TRIP
ON THAT NITROGEN, UH,
AND THAT--AND THAT LITTLE PIG
THAT WENT TO THE FREEZER.
IT'S LIKE CULINARY
RAMBO OVER HERE.
OKAY, SO WE TAKE HEAVY CREAM
AND MILK AND SUGAR.
WE ADD SPLIT VANILLA BEANS
WITH SEEDS INTO THE POT.
WE BRING THAT UP
TO A LIGHT SIMMER.
THEN WE TEMPER IN
OUR EGG YOLKS AND SUGAR.
THEN WE STRAIN IT
AND PUT IT IN THE COOLER.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR BASE,
WHICH IS NOW COOL,
AND THEN WE HAVE
OUR BOURBON.
WE TAKE THE EXTRA PODS...
MMM.
AND WE STUFF 'EM IN THERE,
AND IT BECOMES OUR OWN EXTRACT.
SO YOU GET THE BOURBON IN THERE,
AND YOU GET THE EXTRA...
SPIKE IT.
EXTRA VANILLA.
AND ALL WE'RE GONNA DO AT THIS
POINT IS ADD OUR NITROGEN.
WHOO-HOO!
ARE YOU SEEING THAT?
IT'S COLD.
NEGATIVE 325 DEGREES.
I'M GONNA TALK TO BOB ABOUT--
I SEE HOW HE TAKES OFF
AND LEAVES ME WITH
THE CRAZY MAD SCIENTIST.
I JUST FIGURE HOW
CAN WOODSHOP HAVE ICE CREAM
THAT DOESN'T SMOKE, RIGHT?
WHAT, ARE WE HAVING
A RAVE PARTY DOWN HERE?
HOW MUCH LIQUID NITROGEN
DID YOU ADD IN THERE?
UH, YOU JUST KIND OF ADD IT
TILL IT'S CRUNCHY.
NOW YOU'LL GIVE THIS
A FINAL FREEZE.
YES, LET IT SET UP.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
THAT IS GOOD.
SON OF TATUM O'NEAL.
CREAMY. SUPER VANILLA.
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
FRESH SPOON, PLEASE.
WHAT DOES THIS
GET SERVED WITH?
WITH OUR
MAPLE BOURBON SUNDAE.
LET'S DO IT.
NOW WE'RE DOING OUR,
UH, MAPLE BOURBON SYRUP
JUST IN CASE THERE WASN'T ENOUGH
BOURBON IN THE ICE CREAM.
OH, EXACTLY. THAT'S
WHAT I ALWAYS SAY.
MAPLE SYRUP. ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF KOSHER SALT.
TWO SPLIT SEEDED
VANILLA BEANS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
REDUCE IT BY HALF.
TAKE OUR CUBED BUTTER--
WHISK THAT BUTTER IN.
GOT IT.
WHEN'S THE BOURBON GO IN?
BOURBON GOES IN
AT THE VERY END.
WE DON'T WANT TO COOK
ANY OF THAT KICK AWAY.
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF BOURBON. NOW WE'RE DONE.
THE SUNDAE'S GONNA
TURN INTO A FUN DAY
WITH THAT MUCH BOURBON.
WE'VE GOT OUR BEAUTIFUL
HOUSE-MADE ICE CREAM,
TWO BIG SCOOPS OF THAT.
MICHIGAN MAPLE
BOURBON SYRUP.
(laughing)
OUR HOUSE-SMOKED
SPANISH PEANUTS.
WHIPPED CREAM.
FROM THE COW THAT
YOU MILKED THIS MORNING.
WE DO WHIP IT OURSELVES.
I KNOW YOU DO.
THOSE SMOKED PEANUTS
ARE WHAT MAKE IT.
YEAH.
THAT ADDS ALL
THE DEPTH RIGHT THERE.
DOES THIS COME
IN FEED BAG?
WE'LL SEND YOU HOME WITH SOME.
YOU'VE JUST GOT TO DRIVE FAST.
KILLED IT.
ALL RIGHT.
KILLED IT,
KILLED IT, KILLED IT.
HEADACHE,
HEADACHE, HEADACHE.
WAIT TILL THE BOURBON
HEADACHE TOMORROW.
IS THAT WHAT IT IS?
YEAH, IT'LL COME ON.
WE'RE GONNA GET YOU
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
THAT'S THE LATER ONE.
YOU'RE A GREAT CHEF.
YOU GUYS DO AN OUTSTANDING JOB.
KID ROCK DEFINITELY
SERVED IT UP THE RIGHT WAY.
I WILL BE BACK.
THANKS A LOT.
WE HOPE TO SEE YOU SOON.
JUST ONE MORE BITE.
ONE MORE.
(laughing)
OKAY.
HERE YOU GO.
UP NEXT...
THIS IS WHERE IT'S DONE?
FORGET THE CARS AND THE CRIBS.
SLOW DOWN!
KID'S ROCKING OUT...
WHAT POINT DO WE
START DRINKING?
HELPING OUT...
AND WE CREATE SOME JOBS
IN THIS TOWN.
AND CRANKIN' OUT SOME BREW.
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT
I LIKE ABOUT THE BEER.
(man) OKAY.
EVERYTHING.
"A," IT'S FREE.
(laughing) IT'S FREE.
IT DOESN'T GET
ANY BETTER THAN THIS--
CRUISING AROUND THE DETROIT
AREA WITH KID ROCK,
CHECKING OUT
HIS FAVORITE JOINTS,
AND WE GOT TIME
FOR ONE MORE SPOT,
ABOUT AN HOUR WEST OF DETROIT
IN WEBBERVILLE,
WHERE THIS HOMEGROWN
ROCK 'N' ROLLER
IS DOING HIS OWN VERSION
OF HOME BREWING.
BADASS TRUCK.
JUST LIKE THE BADASS BEER
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT
THAT WAS GIVEN BIRTH TO
RIGHT THERE
IN THE BASEMENT
OF THE CLARKSTON UNION.
WELL, WE OUTGREW THAT,
SO I WANT YOU TAKE YOU
INSIDE THE PLANT HERE
AND GIVE YOU
A LITTLE TOUR.
THIS IS WHERE
IT'S DONE?
IT HAPPENS.
OH, I GOTTA
SEE THIS.
COME ON.
IT STARTED AS A HOBBY...
(man) CHEERS.
BUT IN '09, KID BROUGHT ON
MASTER BREWER BOBBY MASON...
I'M ABOUT READY TO DO
GRAIN OUT OVER HERE.
TO GET IT ROLLING.
SO YOU'RE THE GUY IN CHARGE
OF SUPPORTING HIS HABIT?
I BELIEVE THAT'S
THE WAY IT IS.
OH, THIS IS DANGEROUS.
SO WHAT KIND OF BEER
ARE YOU MAKING HERE?
IT'S AN AMERICAN
LIGHT LAGER,
AND WE JUST DO IT
IN MICHIGAN.
SO HOW DID YOU GUYS
COME TOGETHER?
OKAY, WHILE WE'RE GOING THROUGH
THESE TOUGH ECONOMIC TIMES,
I SAID, "YOU KNOW WHAT?
THERE'S NOT A LOT I CAN DO,
BUT I KNOW A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT BEER,"
SO I SAID, "MAN, I'M GONNA START
AN AMERICAN BEER COMPANY."
WE CREATE SOME JOBS
IN THIS TOWN.
YOU CAN MAKE SOME IMPACT
IN THIS GREATER DETROIT AREA.
I BELIEVE IN TAKING CARE
OF YOUR NEIGHBOR FIRST.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN.
WE START WITH OUR MALTED
BARLEY FROM THE MIDWEST.
WE'RE GONNA FINISH
GRINDING THE GRAIN.
UM, WE HAVE SOME
RED WHEAT IN HERE.
THIS IS THE RED WHEAT?
YEAH, IT'S RED WHEAT. IT
COMES RIGHT FROM MID-MICHIGAN.
AND THEN YOU'RE SHOOTING IT
OVER TO THE TANKS?
YEP.
AND HOW LONG
DOES THE PROCESS--
21 TO 26 DAYS.
AND, UM, YOU CAN ACTUALLY
CHEW ON IT AND TASTE IT.
MM-HMM.
IT TASTES GOOD.
IT'S MALT BARLEY.
SEE, IF YOU HANG OUT
WITH A FOOD DUDE--
IF YOU HANG OUT
WITH A CHEF, RIGHT?
I MEAN, LOOK
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
THEN WE'LL GO UP
ON THE BREW HOUSE,
AND WE'LL BRING THE REST OF THIS
OVER TO THE MASH TUN,
AND YOU CAN SEE
WHAT'S BEING COOKED.
ALL RIGHT.
LET ME PUSH
A BUTTON HERE AND--
OKAY, WHAT'S
HAPPENING NOW?
THE GRAIN--THE BARLEY
WE'RE BRINGING OVER
IN THROUGH THE AUGER SYSTEM
INTO THE MASH TUN.
THIS IS A MIXER.
A COUPLE THOUSAND
POUNDS OF GRAIN IN HERE.
630, 40 GALLONS OF WATER.
I REALLY SEE HOW YOU'RE
JUMPING IN HERE, BOB,
HELPING ME OUT
WITH THESE--
YOU GUYS
ARE DOING FINE.
JUST--JUST LET ME GO.
GO AHEAD, MAN.
AND THEN WE'LL TRANSFER ALL
THIS MASH THAT'S HOT FILTERED,
AND ALL THE SPENT GRAIN
FEEDS THE LOCAL CATTLE.
SO NOW IT MOVES OVER
TO THE BOIL KETTLE.
YES, WE START
TO BRING IT TO A BOIL.
WE ADD A LITTLE BIT OF HOPS
TOWARDS THE END OF THE BOIL,
ABOUT AN HOUR LATER,
AND THAT'S MORE OF A LITTLE BIT
OF A FLAVOR/AROMA HOP.
WHAT POINT DO WE
START DRINKING?
IN JUST A FEW MINUTES.
THEN WE PUMP IT THROUGH
THE, UM, FERMENTER, THE HOSE.
THE YEAST TAKES OVER, AND THEN
WE END UP WITH OUR ALCOHOL.
ALCOHOL.
HEY, ALCOHOL!
HEY, WE'RE BACK!
WE'RE BACK!
IT TAKES ABOUT 26 DAYS
TO GET IT RIGHT,
AND THESE CATS ARE TURNING OUT
ALMOST 20,000 CASES A MONTH,
BUT YOU'VE STILL GOT TO TEST
EVERY BATCH.
i.e. THIS IS
THE FUN PART.
(laughing)
WE'RE GONNA GET SOME BEER
OUT OF HERE, OKAY?
ALL RIGHT.
SO WHAT ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO BE GETTING AT THIS POINT?
IT'S JUST A QUALITY
ASSURANCE CHECK.
WELL, WHAT IF
IT IS SCREWED UP?
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO NOW?
ADD GRAVY?
I'M GONNA NOT SLEEP
VERY GOOD TONIGHT
AND GET IN TOMORROW
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT I CAN DO.
HE'S NOT GONNA HAVE
A GOOD FRIDAY.
(laughing) NO.
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THE BEER.
OKAY.
EVERYTHING.
"A," IT'S FREE.
(laughing) IT'S FREE.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THIS
IS I DON'T FEEL LIKE
I'M HAVING A BOWL OF OATMEAL
AND 16 OTHER INGREDIENTS
AT ONE TIME, AND--AND GRANTED,
PEOPLE LIKE THAT TYPE OF BEER.
THIS IS A REAL NICE
REFRESHING, CRISP BEER.
THAT'S HOW
WE WENT INTO IT.
I SAID, "I WANT BEER
THAT I SEE PEOPLE DRINKING
"IN THE PARKING LOTS
BEFORE THE CONCERTS, YOU KNOW,
WHEN THEY'RE OUT THERE
TAILGATING."
FANTASTIC. BUILDING THE JOBS.
BREWING THE BEER.
ALL-AMERICAN.
KEEPING IT IN MICHIGAN.
THANK YOU.
THANKS A LOT FOR THE TOUR.
THANKS A LOT FOR THE FREE BEER.
CHEERS.
CHEERS, GUYS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR
THE SPECIAL EDITION TOUR
WITH KID ROCK IN MICHIGAN
CHECKING OUT YOUR FAVORITE
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
DON'T WORRY, WE'VE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY,
AND I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YEAH.
SO THE DEAL IS, RIGHT, YOU TEACH
ME HOW TO PLAY THE GUITAR,
I TEACH YOU HOW TO COOK.
ALL RIGHT, BUT I WANT
TO LEARN HOW TO MAKE
A BRONTOSAURUS BURGER.
FINE. I WANT TO LEARN
HOW TO PLAY THE GUITAR
LIKE EDDIE VAN HALEN.
DAMN. I CAN'T PLAY GUITAR
WELL, I CAN'T MAKE
BRONTOSAURUS BURGERS.
(laughing)