I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YEAH, YOU DID.
IT'S SURF AND TURF...
ONE, TWO, THREE,
AND ONE FOR ME.
BETWEEN THE SLICES.
THE PORK BELLY TURNS INTO,
LIKE, MEAT MAYONNAISE.
IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
A SIDEWALK CHEF...
I CALL IT A RESTAURANT. IT JUST
HAPPENS TO HAVE WHEELS ON IT.
GETTIN' FRESH
WITH THE SEAFOOD...
IT'S A SHOVEL BATH.
THERE YOU GO.
AND GETTIN' FUNKY
WITH HIS DANCE MOVES.
IN THE MOTOR CITY,
THE 18,000-SQUARE-FOOT JOINT...
I GOT LOST. I WAS, LIKE,
OVER IN THE WEST WING.
TAKING MADE IN DETROIT...
CRAZY PLACE--
DAIRY, BAKERY, RESTAURANT.
IT'S LIKE
A BRONTOSAURUS BURGER.
TO A RIDICULOUS LEVEL...
IT'S SO LOCAL,
IT COMES FROM THE SAME ADDRESS.
NOT BAD.
AND IN CHICAGO,
THE DOWNTOWN ITALIAN MARKET...
THESE ARE THE ONLY MEATBALLS I
EAT OTHER THAN MY GRANDMOTHER'S.
I'M GONNA TELL HER.
PLEASE DON'T.
CRANKING OUT THE FLAVORS...
♪ OH ♪
DID YOU HEAR THE ANGELS SING?
OF THE SOUTH SIDE.
MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH
TENDER. CRAZY GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
I'M CRUISING THROUGH
THE DOWNTOWN
OF VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA,
JUST A FEW BLOCKS
FROM THE WATER.
NOW THE BUSINESS PEOPLE
IN THIS AREA
ARE LOOKING FOR A QUICK LUNCH.
THE GREAT THING ABOUT THIS
CORNER IS, THEY CAN GET
A QUICK LUNCH THAT'S ALSO
FRESH, LOCAL, AND WILD.
FRESH SEAFOOD.
OH, YEAH.
THAT DOES IT.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
WE'RE LITERALLY
A BLOCK AWAY FROM THE OCEAN.
FINDING ORGANIC FOOD
IN A STREET TRUCK IS NOT EASY.
BUT CHEF AND OWNER JOSH WOLFE
WOULDN'T REALLY CALL THIS
A STREET TRUCK ANYWAY...
I CALL IT A RESTAURANT. IT JUST
HAPPENS TO HAVE WHEELS ON IT.
BECAUSE THIS PLACE
IS A PERMANENT FIXTURE
ON DOWNTOWN VANCOUVER'S
BURRARD AND WEST HASTINGS.
SO HOW DID YOU
PICK THIS CORNER?
FOR ME,
IT WAS REALLY IMPORTANT
TO BE IN A SPOT
WHERE PEOPLE DO LUNCH.
I WANT PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO EAT.
NO PROBLEM.
VANCOUVER'S A CITY THAT REALLY
BELIEVES IN THEIR FOOD.
LOCAL FOOD IS SOMETHING
THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO US.
SO OF COURSE, YOU'VE GOTTA HAVE
THE CANADIAN MASH OF POUTINE.
HOW DO YOU
DESCRIBE IT HERE?
CLASSIC POUTINE--
FRENCH FRIES,
A BEEF GRAVY OR A BROWN GRAVY,
AND CHEESE CURDS.
BUT THIS POUTINE
IS THE FRESH, LOCAL, WILD WAY.
WE'RE NOT GONNA USE
BROWN GRAVY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SEAFOOD GRAVY...
OF COURSE, WE ARE.
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU NOTICED,
BUT THE OCEAN'S
TWO BLOCKS AWAY.
I DIG IT, I DIG IT,
AND YOU GOT PEOPLE
STARTING TO LINE UP.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA COOK?
BUTTER, WE'RE GONNA USE
A LITTLE BIT OF CANOLA OIL.
WE GOT OUR FAT
DOWN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA LAY
OUR BASE FLAVOR LAYER DOWN--
SHALLOTS, GARLIC, A LITTLE
FENNEL--ARE YOU OKAY WITH THAT?
OOH.
CARROTS, A LITTLE CELERY,
GIVE 'EM A LITTLE STIR.
WE'LL GET 'EM SWEATED DOWN
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HIT 'EM
WITH THE LOVE.
THIS IS GONNA
GET RIDICULOUS.
I KNOW, I KNOW,
I KNOW, I KNOW.
CLAMS GOING DOWN.
SO NOW WE NEED THE LIQUID.
GOOD, OLD WHITE WINE,
BAY LEAVES, A LITTLE AROMATICS.
BLACK PEPPER, WHITE PEPPER...
OH.
CORIANDER SEED--
BEAUTIFUL WITH SHELLFISH--
THE JUNIPERS.
JUNIPER.
FANTASTIC.
AND JUST TO ROUND IT OUT,
A LITTLE BIT OF FRESH THYME.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA
SEAL THE DEAL.
LET IT STEAM.
KEEP ALL THE LIQUID IN THERE.
OKAY.
THOSE CLAMS START TO OPEN, WE'RE
GONNA THROW DOWN OUR MUSSELS,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT
TO OVERCOOK ANYTHING.
WE'RE GONNA TRY
AND DO IT ALL RIGHT.
SOMEBODY'S HAS GOT
TO TAKE ALL OF HIS MOVES
AND PUT THIS
TO SOME DISCO MUSIC.
HE HAS GOT
SO MUCH ANIMATION,
I WANT A "STAYING ALIVE,"
I WANT A LITTLE BEE GEES.
I'M GONNA SEPARATE THE LIQUID
FROM THE MUSSELS AND CLAMS,
AND WE'RE GONNA CHILL THOSE DOWN
SO WE CAN HANDLE THEM.
NOW THESE ARE COOLED DOWN
TO WHERE YOU CAN HANDLE 'EM.
LOOK AT THAT
BEAUTIFUL MUSSEL.
SO CLAMS AND MUSSELS,
SHELLS BACK IN.
NEXT UP...
NOW WE NEED SOMETHING
TO PUT ALL OF THOSE
BEAUTIFUL SHELLFISH INTO.
SO WE'RE GONNA
TALK CHOWDER.
SO REALLY,
WE ARE MAKING A CHOWDER...
YEAH, WE ARE MAKING
A CHOWDER.
THAT'S GONNA
GO OVER FRIES.
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S BACON.
THAT'S SMOKED BACON.
OKAY, PORK BELLY, NICE.
EQUAL PART ONION. WE'RE GONNA
START THOSE MELTING DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IN THE SAME
BASE FLAVORS THAT WE USED.
AND WE'RE GONNA SWEAT
ALL THAT OUT.
SO WE'RE RENDERED DOWN.
WE GOT ENOUGH FAT
IN THERE.
NOW WE'LL ADD A LITTLE FLOUR,
BUILD A ROUX.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA STIR IT REAL GOOD,
MAKE SURE EVERYTHING
IS COATED.
WHAT ARE YOU
THROWING IN NEXT?
A LITTLE MORE
OF THAT WHITE WINE.
OKAY.
LIMITED MOISTURE,
MAXIMUM FLAVOR.
I'M GONNA OVEREAT.
I CAN ALREADY TELL.
(laughs)
A LITTLE HEAVY CREAM.
NOW YOU GOT THE NICE RICHNESS
OF THE HEAVY CREAM
WORKING WITH THE ROUX,
BUT IT DOESN'T HAVE
TO BE ALL HEAVY CREAM
IF YOU HAVE A NICE ROUX
IN THERE.
I'M GONNA USE MILK
FOR THE REST OF THAT.
SO THIS IS THE LIQUOR THAT WE
STRAINED OUT FROM ALL THE SHELLS
THAT WE COOKED.
YEAH, YOU DID.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
BRING THIS UP TO A SIMMER.
TO SERVE THIS, WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR PORTION OF GRAVY,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THOSE BEAUTIFUL SHELLFISH
THAT WE PICKED BEFORE.
THAT MUCH SHELLFISH?
YEAH, WHY NOT?
THAT'S MORE SHELLFISH
THAN YOU GET
AT MOST SEAFOOD RESTAURANTS
FOR A NICE PLATE
AT $21.95.
WELL, TELL EVERYONE
YOU KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, FRIES DOWN, AND THAT
GRAVY'S NICE AND BUBBLY HOT.
I'M GONNA THROW YA
A LITTLE PARSLEY TO FINISH IT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
YOU ARE STEPPING INTO
THE RIDICULOUS ZONE.
LOOK AT THE CASCADING
DELICIOUSNESS.
(laughs)
AND, MY FRIEND,
THAT LOOKS DYN-O-MITE.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW HOW DO YOU
ATTACK IT?
DUMP RIGHT IN THERE.
IT'S A SHOVEL BATH.
THERE YOU GO.
SO I JUST--
I WEAR IT.
I'M GONNA TRY TO DO THE OLD,
UH, CHOPSTICK FRENCH FRY.
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S ONE
OF THE NEW METHODS.
THERE WE GO.
MMM. DELICATE FLAVOR,
RICH FLAVOR.
NOT OVERSEASONED.
SUPER CRUNCHY FRIES.
AND LOOK AT ALL
THE SEAFOOD.
LOOK AT THAT
BIG MUSSEL RIGHT THERE.
MMM.
I'VE HAD SOME CRAZY FRIES
IN MY LIFE.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
I'VE EVER HAD SEAFOOD FRIES
AND INCREDIBLY WELL DONE.
HERE WE GO, GUYS. I GOT THOSE
POUTINES YOU'RE DYING FOR.
IN THE WORLD OF POUTINES,
THIS IS...
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
MAKES IT SO GOOD?
GOOD-QUALITY FOOD,
LIKE, YOU CAN TELL
EVERYTHING'S MADE FRESH.
(Josh) FRESH FISH COMES--
A LOT OF IT,
DIRECTLY FROM THE FISHERMEN.
THERE'S BOATS COMING IN
EVERY DAY.
(Guy) YOU'RE A BLOCK AWAY
FROM THE WATER.
I AM. I'M FOUR BLOCKS AWAY
FROM FISHERMAN'S WHARF.
B.C.'s KNOWN FOR SOME
ABSOLUTELY STUNNING OYSTERS.
THESE HAPPEN TO BE SOME OF
THE BIGGEST ONES YOU CAN FIND.
AND HE'S PILING 'EM UP
PO'BOY STYLE
FOR A CHICKEN-FRIED
OYSTER SANDWICH
WITH TRAILER-MADE TARTAR SAUCE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
BUTTERMILK.
THE BUTTERMILK HAS
A REALLY NICE ACIDITY TO IT.
A CREAMY ACIDITY.
CREAMY ACIDITY.
WHICH MIXES WELL
WITH THIS, OKAY.
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH.
A LITTLE OF MY FAVORITE
HOT SAUCE.
I KNOW.
IT'S SRIRACHA, JUST A LITTLE,
MAYBE A LITTLE MORE.
OKAY.
OYSTERS ARE GOING DOWN.
YOU TAKE 'EM.
WE MARINATE 'EM.
IN THE FRIDGE
TO GO TO MARINATE.
OKAY, AND THEN WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DREDGE 'EM IN?
JUST A LITTLE SIMPLE FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THESE THINGS.
THOSE ARE BIG BOYS.
HOW MANY COME
IN AN ORDER?
THREE, BUT I'M GONNA EAT ONE
OFF THE EDGE THERE
WHILE YOU'RE EATING
THE SANDWICH.
OH, IS THAT HOW
THAT'S GONNA WORK?
I'M A LITTLE SELFISH
RIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
I'M THINKING ABOUT ME.
AND THEN WE'LL
FRY SOME OYSTERS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA COOK
SOME OYSTERS. REAL SIMPLE.
DOWN INTO
SOME CANOLA OIL.
YOU SHOULD SEE THOSE.
GORGEOUS. READY?
PULL 'EM.
A LITTLE SALT IN.
BOOM, WE'RE GONNA SERVE 'EM UP.
BEAUTIFUL SOFT, TOASTED BUN,
TARTAR SAUCE ON BOTH SIDES.
ONE, TWO, THREE,
AND ONE FOR ME.
ALL RIGHT.
ROMAINE LETTUCE.
I LOVE SHREDDED ROMAINE LETTUCE
ON THIS ONE. SIMPLE.
THAT'S ALL YOU.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, OH. (laughs)
I KNOW THAT LOOK.
DELICIOUS.
THIS IS SIMPLE. IT'S RICH.
IT'S DELICATE.
NICE TARTAR SAUCE TO COMPLEMENT
AND JUST A NICE LITTLE CRUNCH
ON THE OUTSIDE
OF A MONSTER OF AN OYSTER.
YOU KILLED IT
COMPLETELY, MAN.
IT'S ACTUALLY
MY FAVORITE SANDWICH.
THE HOMEMADE TARTAR SAUCE
IS OUT OF THIS WORLD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
MMM.
SHE'S SAYING
IT'S VERY DELICIOUS.
THE SEAFOOD'S INCREDIBLY FRESH.
IS THAT CORRECT?
YES.
CONGRATS, MAN.
YOU ROCK IT OUT BIG TIME.
CHEERS. THANK YOU. CHEERS.
THE GUY'S BANANAS.
WILD, RIDICULOUS,
AND OUT OF CONTROL
OR FRESH, LOCAL, AND WILD,
YOU CALL IT.
COMING UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO MIDTOWN DETROIT...
YEAH.
FOR SCRATCH-MADE BRISKET...
WE WILL LOAD
THAT SANDWICH UP.
AND PORK SALAD WITH A KICK.
HOT SAUCE JELLY BEANS.
I'M GLAD THAT YOU EXPLAINED IT
TO PEOPLE BEFORE THEY GET IT,
BECAUSE I'D SWEAR THAT'S
A CHERRY TOMATO, THEN THEY
WOULD BITE INTO IT, I THINK
THEY WOULD BE QUITE ALARMED.
(laughs)
I'M HERE IN MIDTOWN DETROIT
IN AN UP-AND-COMING NEIGHBORHOOD
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S OWNED BY
A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM.
NOW THIS PLACE IS HUGE--
OVER 18,000 SQUARE FEET,
AND OVER 50% OF THAT
IS KITCHENS.
THAT'S BECAUSE THEY'VE
GOT THEIR OWN DAIRY.
THEY'RE MAKING THEIR OWN CHEESE.
THEY GOT THEIR OWN BAKERY
BAKING THEIR OWN BREADS,
AND THEIR KITCHEN IS SERVING
OVER 120,000 PEOPLE A YEAR.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
THIS
IS THE TRAFFIC JAM AND SNUG.
ALL RIGHT, SMELT UP.
HAS IT ALWAYS BEEN THIS BIG?
I GOT LOST.
VEGETARIAN TEX-MEX BURGER.
I MEAN,
THEY'VE BEEN HERE FOREVER...
MEDIUM CHOWDER.
THEY'VE ALWAYS DONE SOMETHING
THAT'S A LITTLE ON THE EDGE.
ALL RIGHTY,
HERE COMES THE JELLY BEANS.
THAT'S WHY I KEEP
COMING BACK HERE.
EVERYBODY KNOWS
WHAT T.J.'S IS.
SURE, BUT EVEN THE REGULARS
ARE STUMPED BY THE NAME.
DO YOU KNOW WHY IT'S CALLED
TRAFFIC JAM AND SNUG?
I'VE OFTEN WONDERED
ABOUT THAT.
GREAT QUESTION.
AND PEOPLE HAVE BEEN ASKING
SINCE THE ORIGINAL OWNER
OPENED IT UP IN 1965.
A SNUG REFERS TO A SMALL
ICE CREAM PARLOR UP FRONT.
ONE OF HIS FRIENDS SAYS,
"HEY, IF IT GOES OFF RIGHT,
THERE'S GONNA BE A TRAFFIC JAM
OF PEOPLE TRYING TO GET IN
HERE," AND IT STUCK.
SO WE BECAME
TRAFFIC JAM AND SNUG.
AND FOLKS ARE STILL
JAMMING THE PLACE
SINCE HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
CAROLYN HOWARD AND SCOTT LOWELL
TOOK OVER IN '99...
(woman) HERE'S
THE SMOKED TURKEY REUBEN.
AND STARTED MAKING ALMOST
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
PROBABLY ONE OF
THE MORE REWARDING ASPECTS
OF HAVING THIS PLACE.
LIKE THIS FAN FAVORITE...
HERE'S THAT BRISKET SANDWICH.
OH, IT'S WONDERFUL.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
A BARBEQUED PANINI.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH BRISKET,
DRY-RUB IT.
YEAH, PAPRIKA,
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR...
KOSHER SALT...
ADD SOME BLACK PEPPER,
GRANULATED GARLIC, CUMIN.
CUMINO.
FINISH WITH
A LITTLE THYME.
FRESH THYME.
YOU GROW THAT YOURSELF?
WE PUT IN A ROOFTOP GARDEN
THIS YEAR.
WE'RE ALSO
MINING OUR OWN ORE
TO HAMMER OUT
OUR OWN POTS AND PANS.
BRING THAT OVER HERE.
SO A NICE
TRIMMED BRISKET,
NICE DRY RUB,
BACK IN THE PAN,
REST THREE HOURS,
AND THEN WE'LL BRING IT BACK
AND THROW IT ON THE FLATTOP
AND SEAR IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO WE'RE GONNA HIT THE FLATTOP
WITH A LITTLE OIL.
(sizzling)
YEAH.
GET THE BRISKET
RIGHT ON TO SEAR.
GOT A NICE SEAR.
WE'RE GONNA PULL THAT OFF.
BRING THIS OVER HERE.
MAKE A BRAISING LIQUID.
HOMEMADE CHICKEN STOCK.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU GUYS DON'T MAKE?
UH, I DON'T THINK SO.
OUR SLOGAN IS, IT'S SO LOCAL,
IT COMES FROM THE SAME ADDRESS.
NOT BAD.
HERE COMES
THE FLAVORING AGENT.
THIS IS OUR HOUSE-BREWED
DOPPELBOCK BEER.
IT'S GONNA ADD BODY
TO THE BRAISING LIQUID.
STANDARD MIREPOIX--
ONION IN, CARROTS NEXT,
CELERY NEXT, BAY LEAF,
FRESH THYME.
IT'S GOING TO COME
TO A LIGHT SIMMER.
YOU POUR IT OVER THE TOP,
HIT IT WITH FOIL,
INTO THE OVEN,
WHAT TEMPERATURE?
ABOUT 325 ABOUT 3 1/2.
3 1/2 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT, PULL IT OUT.
LET'S SLICE IT UP.
SO WE'LL GET
OUR BARBECUE SAUCE GOING--
KETCHUP, APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
BROWN SUGAR.
THE SECRET INGREDIENT
IS FENNEL SEED.
ALL RIGHT, GET THAT IN.
CARAMELIZED RED ONIONS.
YEP.
WE SERVE IT
ON OUR HOMEMADE PANINI ROLL,
AND WE WILL LOAD
THAT SANDWICH UP.
THIS WILL FEED, LIKE,
A FAMILY OF SIX.
LID ON.
YOU ALREADY HIT THE BREAD
IN THE PANINI,
SO YOU GOT THAT
NICE LITTLE CRUST TO IT.
THERE YOU GO--
BRAISED BEEF PANINI.
WHOO.
IT'S LIKE
A BRONTOSAURUS BURGER.
THE PANINI BREAD
IS ABOUT FANTASTIC.
IT'S GOT GREAT CRUNCH.
IT'S GOT FLAVOR.
THE BEEF IS SUPER TENDER,
THE BARBECUE SAUCE,
A LITTLE ON THE SWEET SIDE,
LIKE A KANSAS CITY-STYLE.
GREAT JOB.
(woman) BEEF BRISKET PANINI.
IT'S A GUILTY PLEASURE ORDERING
THE WHOLE THING AT LUNCH.
WHEN YOU ORDER THAT,
IF YOU CAN EAT THE WHOLE THING,
THEY DO HAVE A NAPPING CENTER
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
THE FOOD?
HOMEMADE WITH A TWIST.
THEY'VE BEEN VERY CREATIVE
FROM THE GET-GO.
SO, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
AS WE TOUR THE COUNTRY ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES,"
OF COURSE, WHO WOULD I RUN INTO?
MY FAMILY, MY COUSINS.
AND, ROB, WHAT WERE YOU
ENJOYING?
(Rob)
CRAB CAKES. FANTASTIC.
MY NEW FAVORITE THING
IS THE PORK SALAD.
IT'S GREAT.
IT'S DIFFERENT, TOO.
YOU DON'T USUALLY GET...
PORK CUTLETS...
RIGHT.
MIXED IN WITH SALAD.
WITH A SPICY KIND OF JELLY BEAN
ON THE SIDE.
YEAH, A JELLY BEAN.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
ALL RIGHT, WE ARE GOING TO MAKE
A GARNISH FOR A SALAD.
THE GARNISH IS GOING TO BE
HOT SAUCE JELLY BEANS.
OKEYDOKEY.
YOU LOOK WORRIED.
NO.
PRETTY SIMPLE. WE'RE GONNA
START WITH HOT SAUCE.
YOU'RE FROM DETROIT,
YOU USE FRANK'S.
AND IF YOU'RE NOT,
YOU USE...
I THINK YOU
SHOULD USE FRANK'S.
OKAY, LET'S ADD SOME HONEY.
AS SOON AS YOU GOT THAT GOING,
YOU'RE GOING TO ADD SIMPLE
CORNSTARCH MIXTURE.
A LITTLE SLURRY.
GETTING TIGHT FAST.
IT'S LIKE A FINE LINE
BETWEEN SUCCESS AND DISASTER.
OKAY, SO GET A LITTLE OIL
ON YOUR SPOON.
(Guy) SO IT JUST SLIDES
RIGHT OFF, OKAY.
YEAH,
INTO THE LITTLE MOLD.
SO THIS WILL COOL DOWN,
AND THESE WILL FORM.
AND THEN THEY JUST POP OUT.
THEY'RE GREAT.
THEY'RE GOOD TO GO.
SO WHERE ARE WE?
WE'RE GOING TO GRIND THE SPICES
FOR THE PORK LOIN SALAD--
SZECHUAN PEPPERCORNS,
STAR ANISE,
CORIANDER, FENNEL SEED,
AND CLOVE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD CINNAMON,
ALLSPICE, WHITE PEPPER,
CARDAMOM,
QUITE A BIT OF GINGER.
WOW.
ADD A COUPLE TABLESPOONS
TO THE FLOUR.
SET UP THE ASSEMBLY LINE.
WE'LL DREDGE THE PORK
INTO THE FLOUR,
INTO THE EGG WASH,
AND THEN OVER TO THE PANKO.
CORRECT.
DIG IT.
A LITTLE PAN SAUTé ON 'EM?
YEAH.
A LITTLE BIT OF OIL IN.
LAY THE PORK LOIN DOWN.
GET IT NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN
ON BOTH SIDES.
YEP.
AND THEN
WE'LL MAKE THE SALAD.
YOU GET THE PORK DOWN
ON THE PLATE FIRST,
AND THEN WE'LL JUST
MIX UP THE SALAD.
LETTUCE IN, ARUGULA,
SUNFLOWER SEED SHOOTS--
THOSE ARE GROWN
IN DETROIT--
RED ONION...
WATERMELON BALLS.
ADD STRAWBERRIES, BEAUTIFUL
RASPBERRIES. ADD BLUEBERRIES.
ADD OUR DRESSING.
ALL RIGHT, GIVE IT A NICE MIX.
AND LADLE THAT ON.
WE HAVE TO ADD
OUR FINAL INGREDIENT...
YES.
HOT SAUCE JELLY BEANS.
THEY LOOK LIKE
LITTLE PLUM TOMATOES.
SO WE'LL JUST PUT THESE
AROUND.
AND THERE YOU GO--
PORK LOIN SALAD.
VERY NICE.
MMM.
GET A LITTLE OF THE GUILTY
PLEASURE WITH THE FRIED PORK,
BUT THEN YOU BACK IT UP WITH
A BUNCH OF HEALTHY INGREDIENTS.
SPROUTS ARE MY FAVORITE.
BUT I THINK THE FREAKY ONE
OF THE WHOLE THING...
(laughs)
IS THAT LITTLE GEM.
THAT'S HOT.
DEFINITELY GETS HOT.
I'M GLAD THAT YOU EXPLAINED IT
TO PEOPLE BEFORE THEY GET IT,
BECAUSE I'D SWEAR THAT'S
A CHERRY TOMATO, THEN THEY
WOULD BITE INTO IT, I THINK
THEY WOULD BE QUITE ALARMED.
(laughs)
CREATIVE.
(man)
PORK TENDERLOIN SALAD.
THE COMBINATION, I THINK,
OF THE BREADED PORK TENDERLOIN
AS WELL AS THE FRESH FRUIT
MAKES IT JUST UNIQUE.
DID YOU TRY
THE JELLY BEAN?
I DID. IT WAS GOOD.
A LITTLE HOT.
THE FOOD'S AUTHENTIC.
THE PLACE IS AUTHENTIC.
I ALWAYS WILL LOVE THIS PLACE
AND COME BACK TO IT.
IT WAS COOL
BEFORE MIDTOWN WAS COOL.
CRAZY PLACE--
18,000 SQUARE FEET,
DAIRY, BAKERY, RESTAURANT.
NICE JOB, YOU GUYS.
THANKS A LOT FOR HAVING ME.
OUR PLEASURE, MAN.
THANK YOU.
THANKS SO MUCH.
YOU BET.
UP NEXT...
IT'S GONNA BE
THIS BIG AROUND.
WE'RE HEADED
TO DOWNTOWN CHICAGO...
THAT LOOKS LIKE A FREAKY
SAGE PESTO RIGHT THERE.
FOR PORK
INSIDE PORK PERFECTION.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT SHOULD BE ILLEGAL.
SO I'M HERE IN CHICAGO
ABOUT 1/2 MILE WEST
OF SOLDIER FIELD
IN AN AREA THAT USED
TO BE A BUNCH OF WAREHOUSES.
WELL, THEN IT TURNED
INTO A BUNCH OF CONDOS
AND A BUNCH OF BUSINESSES,
SO IT'S LIKE A NEW NEIGHBORHOOD.
SO WHAT'S A NEW NEIGHBORHOOD
NEED? EXACTLY.
A COUPLE ITALIAN BUDDIES
FROM THE SOUTH SIDE
TO ROLL OVER TO THIS SIDE
AND OPEN UP AN ITALIAN MARKET.
THIS IS PANOZZO'S.
PAM, HERE'S YOUR LASAGNA.
IT'S LIKE GOING TO A GOURMET
RESTAURANT, BUT IT'S A DELI.
ITALIANO.
THESE ARE THE ONLY MEATBALLS I
EAT OTHER THAN MY GRANDMOTHER'S.
I'M GONNA TELL HER.
PLEASE DON'T.
PROSCIUTTO AND MOZZARELLA.
BEING HALF ITALIAN,
A LOT OF THESE RECIPES
HAVE BEEN IN MY FAMILY
FOR GENERATIONS.
IT'S THOSE SOUTH SIDE
ITALIAN CLASSICS
THAT MIKE PANOZZO
AND TONY GIERCZYK
WANTED TO KEEP ALIVE
WHEN THEY OPENED THE JOINT
IN 2007.
THERE WASN'T
ANYTHING LIKE THAT
WHEN MY WIFE AND I
MOVED IN DOWN HERE,
AND SO WE DECIDED,
WOULDN'T IT BE COOL TO OPEN
A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
WHERE EVERYBODY WOULD COME.
THE KIND OF SANDWICHES
YOU USED TO GET
ON THE SOUTH SIDE.
EXACTLY.
TO MAKE THAT HAPPEN, THEY
BROUGHT IN CHEF JOHN ASBATY.
JOHN WAS THE DRIVER
BEHIND THE MENU.
HE'S SO PASSIONATE
ABOUT FOOD.
A PASSION THAT GOES WAY BEYOND
YOUR TYPICAL DELI CLASSICS.
PORCHETTA CRESCENTINA.
FINALLY, I FOUND A PLACE THAT'S
COOKING PROPERLY PORCHETTA.
ALL RIGHT, MAN,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE ARE MAKING PORCHETTA.
IT'S GONNA BE
THIS BIG AROUND.
NICE BIG, OLD PIECE
OF PORK BELLY HERE.
SO FIRST, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE CURE FOR THIS PORK BELLY--
SOME TOASTED FENNEL SEED,
TOASTED BLACK PEPPERCORNS,
TOASTED CORIANDER SEED,
FRESH BAY LEAVES.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND THIS
IN OUR PSEUDO SPICE GRINDER.
AND YOU DON'T
HAVE A LID?
I DON'T HAVE
A LID.
THIS IS GONNA GET COMBINED
WITH SOME KOSHER SALT.
WE'RE GONNA GENEROUSLY
COVER THIS.
OH, ALL THAT TOASTED FENNEL
JUST SMELLS LIKE WILLY WONKA
LICORICE TOWN.
NOW IT GOES IN THE COOLER
AND CURES FOR TWO DAYS.
WE HAVE A PORTION
OF THE PORK BUTT HERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MARINATE IT
FOR THE PORCHETTA.
GOT IT.
FOR THE MARINADE,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
SOME FRESH GARLIC,
SOME FRESH SAGE...
OOH.
FRESH ROSEMARY,
FRESHLY GRATED ORANGE ZEST,
PORK BELLY CURE.
GOT IT.
KIND OF LIKE A BOMB TECH
WITH THIS.
NOW WE'RE JUST
GONNA COVER THIS.
IT LOOKS LIKE A FREAKY
SAGE PESTO RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW THE SHOULDER
GOES IN THE COOLER FOR TWO DAYS.
SO WE GOT THE PORK BELLY
THAT WAS RINSED...
OKAY.
CURED FOR TWO DAYS.
WE'RE GONNA SCORE THE SKIN ON A
DIAGONAL SLIGHTLY INTO THE FAT.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
FLIP THIS OVER.
WE'RE GONNA WRAP THE SHOULDER
IN THE BELLY.
OKAY.
TIE IT UP,
AND ROAST IT.
HOW LONG?
I GO 450
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
CRISP UP THAT SKIN.
AND THEN 350
FOR ANOTHER 3 OR 4 HOURS.
THIS IS THE FINISHED
PORCHETTA.
I'M JUST GONNA
REMOVE THE STRINGS.
WE'RE GONNA GO
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
♪ OH ♪
DID YOU HEAR
THE ANGELS SING?
NOW WE SLICE OFF
A PIECE.
MMM.
MELT-IN-YOUR-MOUTH
TENDER.
CRAZY GOOD.
NO WONDER YOU GUYS
GO THROUGH SO MUCH OF THIS. OH.
THE CRESCENTINA BREAD
FOR THIS PORK-ON-PORK SANDWICH
STARTS WITH A YEASTY DOUGH
THAT JOHN PUNCHES,
PORTIONS, AND THEN
FRY, BABY, FRY.
IT'S A CROSS BETWEEN FRY BREAD
AND PIZZA DOUGH.
PRETTY MUCH.
READY FOR THE ASSEMBLY.
I SLICE THE BREAD IN HALF,
THE PORCHETTA.
LOOK AT THAT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF PICKLED FENNEL.
AND THEN IN THE CONVECTION OVEN
FOR ABOUT SIX TO SEVEN MINUTES.
THE BREAD GETS CRISPY.
THE PORCHETTA FAT RENDERS
INTO THE BREAD,
AND THIS IS THE FINISHED
PORCHETTA CRESCENTINA.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
MMM.
THE EXTRA YEASTY BREAD,
IT IS THE BOMB.
THAT HERBACEOUS RUB
WITH THAT FENNEL
CUTS THE SWEETNESS.
THE PORK BELLY FAT
TURNS INTO, LIKE,
MEAT MAYONNAISE.
JUST LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
NICE JOB, CHEF, SERIOUSLY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I MEAN,
THAT SHOULD BE ILLEGAL.
BUT THE QUESTION I GOT IS,
DO YOU HAVE MEATBALLS?
YEAH.
THEY GOT MEATBALLS.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE AT PANOZZO'S IN CHICAGO,
AND WE'RE GONNA
MAKE MEATBALLS.
YOU CAN'T MISS THIS.
IT BETTER BE A GOOD MEATBALL.
WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE AT PANOZZO'S IN CHICAGO,
HANGING OUT
WITH CHEF JOHN.
MAN, THIS DUDE'S
BEEN TEARING IT UP.
BUT NOW HE TELLS ME
HE'S GOT THE BOMB MEATBALL.
MEATBALL SANDWICH.
SHE'S HOLDING THE MEATBALL
SANDWICH IN ONE HAND
AND CUTTING THE OTHER ONE
WITH THE FORK.
THEY'VE GOT A SPECIAL INGREDIENT
IN THE MEATBALLS
THAT KEEPS ME COMING BACK.
I AM A MEATBALL-MAKING
MACHINE.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S DO IT THEN.
WHAT ARE WE
STARTING WITH?
THE FIRST STEP,
WE MAKE A VEGETABLE SOFRITO
FOR THE MEATBALL MIX.
OF COURSE WE DO.
SO WE TAKE
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
YELLOW ONION,
SOME CHOPPED CELERY...
I LIKE IT.
KOSHER SALT,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
CRUSHED RED CHILI FLAKES.
WHOA.
WE'RE IN THE SOUTH NOW, MAN.
SO THIS GETS COOKED DOWN
TILL THE VEGETABLES
ARE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY SOFT.
AND THIS IS ALL THE SOFRITO
THAT'S JUST GONNA BE MIXED IN
AND ADDED WITH THE MEAT.
YEAH.
SALT-PACKED CAPERS,
FRESH GARLIC,
AND CALABRIAN CHILIES...
YOU'RE TRYING IT FIRST.
CURRANTS.
CURRENTLY,
HOW MANY DID YOU ADD?
NOW THE TOMATO SAUCE.
HOW MUCH LONGER
IS IT GONNA STAY ON?
TWO TO THREE HOURS.
DIG IT.
SO WE HAVE
ALL THE CAST OF CHARACTERS.
THE FIRST STEP, SOAKING HALF
OF THE BREADCRUMBS IN MILK,
SOME BEATEN EGGS,
AND NEXT,
SOME OF THE COOLED
VEGETABLE SOFRITO.
THEN THE SOAKED BREADCRUMBS.
LOOK AT ALL THAT MILK THAT
GOT INCORPORATED INTO THIS.
SO YOU GET ALL THAT
EXTRA MOISTURE.
YOU'RE NOT JUST RELYING
ON ALL THE FAT.
AND SOME
PECORINO ROMANO CHEESE.
AND THIS GETS MIXED
BY HAND.
TELL ME WHEN YOU'RE
AT THIS STAGE OF THINGS,
YOU DON'T REALLY JUST THINK
ABOUT PICKING UP A BIG GLOB...
(whispering)
CHUCKING IT AT SOMEBODY.
OKAY, SO AS SOON AS THIS
IS INCORPORATED,
OUR MILD BULK SAUSAGE.
(normal voice)
THIS IS ALL PORK.
100% PORK.
THIS GETS MIXED BY HAND.
AND ROLLED INTO 3-OUNCE BALLS,
FRIED AND FINISHED
IN HOUSE-MADE TOMATO SAUCE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SAUCE
FROM THE MEATBALLS...
BANANA PEPPERS...
A LITTLE BED
OF PROVOLONE,
AND OUR MEATBALLS.
MAN, I'M NOT
GONNA BE ABLE TO MOVE.
A LITTLE MORE SAUCE,
A LITTLE MORE BANANA PEPPERS.
THERE YOU GO--
MEATBALL SANDWICH.
AS BIG AS MY HEAD.
MMM.
YOU'VE GOT GOOD SPICE,
AND THE YOU GET THOSE LITTLE
CURRANTS IN THERE
THAT ADD LITTLE BITS
OF SWEETNESS.
BREAD'S REALLY NICE.
CHEESE WORKS OUT PERFECT.
A LITTLE ACID
FROM THE PEPPER.
I DIG IT, MAN.
MMM. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
TOO MUCH OF A NICE JOB.
THIS IS A VERY SACRED
SANDWICH.
SACRED.
(man) MEATBALL SANDWICH.
I LOVE EVERYTHING IN HERE,
BUT THIS IS MY FAVORITE.
WE COME FROM INDIANA
JUST TO EAT AT PANOZZO'S.
WHEN WE FIRST MOVED
INTO THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
WE DISCOVERED PANOZZO'S
RIGHT ON THE CORNER,
AND WE'VE BEEN COMING EVERY WEEK
EVER SINCE.
I'M A FIRM BELIEVER IN
EVERYTHING HAPPENS FOR A REASON,
AND HERE WE ARE.
GOOD JOB, GUYS.
THANK YOU.
(both) THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND THE RECIPES
FOR SOME OF THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(sirens wailing)
THEY'RE COMING
TO GET ME.
DON'T NOD YES.