HEY, THERE! I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
♪ DUN-DUN DUN-DUN ♪
I'M JUMPING INTO THE OCTAGON...
MOO!
(amplified voice)
FOR MEAT... MANIA... ONE...
(bell dings)
LEG, LEG, THIGH!
UNDER THE NUMBER 7
IN QUEENS, NEW YORK...
(man) LOOK AT THAT.
ARROZ CON POLLO.
A LEGIT CUBAN JOINT...
UH-HUH.
GETTING MY BUDDY CARL'S
SEAL OF APPROVAL.
YI!
IN CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA...
THE MOOSE IS LOOSE.
IT'S TAXIDERMY...
(gunshots)
WE DON'T REALLY CATER
TO VEGETARIANS.
(man) DUCK CLUB WITH FRIES.
(bell dings)
MEETS TRIPLE-DECKER DUCK...
YOU SHOULD TRY THAT...
WHEN YOU MAKE YOUR OWN.
(laughs)
AND A PORK EXTRAVAGANZA.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
ME AT THE BEACH.
AND VANCOUVER, B.C....
THERE YOU GO.
(laughs)
A BAR...
A SAUSAGE FACTORY...
PARTY TIME. WHOA.
AND A MATCH...
MMM.
MADE IN HEAVEN.
WHAT KIND OF BAR DOESN'T
SELL THEIR OWN SAUSAGES?
YOU'RE MISSING IT IF YOU'RE
NOT SELLING YOUR OWN SAUSAGES.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
SOMETHING'S MISSING.
OKAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN QUEENS, NEW YORK,
LOOKING FOR
SOME OUTRAGEOUS CUBAN FOOD.
I GOTTA CALL IN THE AUTHORITIES.
ONE OF MY BUDDIES
HAS GOT THE LOWDOWN
ON THE CULINARY SHOWDOWN,
SO I RING UP CARL RUIZ,
FANTASTIC CUBAN CHEF
HERE IN NEW YORK.
WE CALL HIM THE CUBAN.
NOW... WHAT'S THIS PLACE CALLED?
RINCON CRIOLLO.
AND IT'S THE BOMB?
LEGIT.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
SHRIMP IN SPANISH SAUCE.
THIS IS THE MECCA OF CUBAN FOOD.
IT'S DELICIOUS EVERY TIME.
ROAST PORK.
CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF IT.
YEAH.
AND THAT'S THE BAD THING
ABOUT IT...
IS YOU CAN'T
GET ENOUGH OF IT.
VACA FRITA.
(man) YOU KNOW YOU'RE WALKING
INTO A REAL CUBAN RESTAURANT.
THESE ARE OWNERS
THAT LIVED THE LIFE IN CUBA,
CAME HERE TO THE UNITED STATES
AND OPENED THIS GREAT PLACE.
THERE WAS ONE IN CUBA.
THE ORIGINAL ONE WAS BORN
IN 1950 BY MY GRANDFATHER,
WHO STARTED THE BUSINESS.
WHERE DO ALL THE RECIPES
COME FROM?
RECIPES ALL COME
FROM MY TÍO BALDO.
"TÍO" HAS GOT
TO BE "UNCLE."
YES, TÍO BALDO IS MY
GRANDFATHER'S YOUNGER BROTHER.
¿CÓMO ESTÁ MI FAMILIA?
THAT'D BE RENÉ ACOSTA,
WHO STILL KEEPS
AN EYE ON THE JOINT
AND LETS GREAT-NEPHEW RUDY...
GREEN BELL PEPPER AND ONIONS.
RUN THE KITCHEN,
ON ONE CONDITION--
DON'T TOUCH THOSE RECIPES.
JUST LIKE THE FOOD
MY GRANDPARENTS USED TO MAKE.
IT'S EXTREMELY AUTHENTIC.
BUT IF YOU'RE TALKING
REAL CUBAN...
ARROZ CON POLLO.
YOU GOTTA KILL IT
WITH THIS CLASSIC.
ARROZ CON POLLO.
ALL RIGHT, CHEF.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
ARROZ CON POLLO.
RICE WITH CHICKEN.
YOU TELL ME
THIS IS THE BOMB,
AND THIS IS THE ONE DISH
IN PARTICULAR THAT YOU SAY
YOU CAN REALLY JUDGE
A GREAT CUBAN RESTAURANT BY.
WHAT MAKES
GREAT ARROZ CON POLLO?
WHAT MAKES IT GOOD IS THE FACT
YOU GET ALL THE FLAVORS
ALL TOGETHER,
ALL JOINED INTO ONE,
NOT SPICY AT ALL, SEASONED.
FIRST THING WE DO IS WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME EXTRA-VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
(sizzling)
ADD IN OUR CHICKEN...
A WHOLE CHICKEN,
BONES AND EVERYTHING.
THEN YOU ADD IN JUST
SOME REGULAR SPANISH ONION.
THEN YOU GO WITH SOME GREEN
BELL PEPPER, AND THAT'S VERY...
SPECIFIC IN SOFRITO.
KEY. KEY. CORRECT.
THAT'S A MAKE-IT-OR-BREAK-IT
INGREDIENT.
WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA ADD
A COUPLE MORE KEY INGREDIENTS...
OKAY.
WHICH IS
OUR TOMATO SAUCE.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS OUR HOMEMADE
GARLIC SAUCE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
THROW IN SOME WHITE WINE.
YOU HAVE A COOKING WINE
THAT YOU GUYS USE.
CORRECT.
'CAUSE IF YOU USE,
LIKE, A SAUVIGNON BLANC,
THAT WOULDN'T BE
FOLLOWING THE...
MY GREAT-UNCLE SAYS
THIS IS WHAT WE GOTTA USE.
CAN'T USE ANYTHING ELSE.
AND THEN TO FINISH IT...
A NICE BOTTLE OF BEER.
OKAY.
THIS AMOUNT GOES IN THERE,
AND THE REST, I DRINK.
THAT'S THE WAY IT SHOULD BE.
(chuckles)
ALL OF IT GOES IN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND ADD SOME SPICES--
GROUND BAY LEAF, CUMIN,
WHITE PEPPER, OREGANO.
CHICKEN BASE GOES IN. LOOK AT
THE COLOR OF THAT THING. WOW.
SEE THAT FROM MARS.
IS THIS DISH
MADE ONCE A DAY?
NOT AT ALL.
THIS IS MADE TO ORDER.
THIS PARTICULAR ORDER'S
FOR TWO PEOPLE.
THAT'S FOR TWO PEOPLE?
THE WAY YOU SEE IT
COOKING RIGHT NOW,
THIS SAME POT GETS
DELIVERED TO THE TABLE.
ADD PARCOOKED RICE.
HAS TO BE SHORT-GRAIN RICE.
OKAY, SO THAT'S--THAT'S WHAT
SPEEDS IT UP A LITTLE BIT,
IS THAT YOU GOT
A LITTLE PARBOILED RICE.
CORRECT.
IT TOOK SOME CONVINCING
TO GET MY GREAT-UNCLE
TO DO IT LIKE THIS, THOUGH.
(gravelly voice)
"THE WAY WE DID IT BACK HOME..."
HE'LL APPRECIATE THAT.
IMPRESSION WILL GO OVER WELL...
IN PERSON.
AFTER HE SMACKS ME
IN THE HEAD.
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME BIJOL.
"BIJOL"?
BIJOL, SÍ.
WE USE IT TO GIVE IT
THAT NICE YELLOW COLOR
THAT THE ARROZ CON POLLO HAS.
IT'S GOT A BUNCH OF,
UH, ANNATTO.
(whistles)
ANOTHER FESTIVE NEON.
OKAY, THERE'S THAT
BEAUTIFUL COLOR THAT I SEE.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
YES, SIR.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
SO, CUBAN, THIS IS A SMELL
THAT YOU WOULD HAVE ON SUNDAYS
AT YOUR HOUSE
WHEN YOU WERE A KID?
YEAH, THIS,
PLUS SOME SCREAMING.
AND NOW YOU'RE GONNA TAKE IT,
POP IT IN THE OVEN FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
COVERED?
25--COVERED, YES.
WE READY?
WE'RE READY.
LET'S SEE THIS. I LIKE
THAT PERFECTLY FITTING LID.
PERFECT.
(chuckles)
LOOK AT THAT.
TWO PEOPLE EAT THIS?
TWO--
TWO CUBANS--
SEVEN REGULAR PEOPLE.
(chuckles)
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GARNISH IT
WITH SOME GREEN PEAS.
WE DON'T COOK THOSE
IN THERE,
BECAUSE THEY WOULD
JUST FALL APART.
CORRECT.
AND SOME RED BELL PEPPER.
JUST REGULAR ROASTED
RED BELL PEPPER.
REGULAR ROASTED
LOOK AT THIS.
FEED AN ARMY.
EXACTLY HOW MY GRANDMOTHER USED
TO MAKE IT AFTER FOUR MOJITOS.
WHAT'S UP WITH
GIVING HIM MORE?
CUBAN.
HE'S CUBAN.
I WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT,
EXCEPT FOR THE FACT
THAT THEY SAID IT TOGETHER.
(Carl and Rudy laugh)
IT'S RICH,
IT'S CREAMY...
I GET THE CHICKEN,
I GET THE RICE,
I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SOFRITO,
BUT NOTHING
IS OVERWHELMING.
NOT ONE ITEM IS TAKING,
LIKE, THE LEAD IN THIS.
(blows air)
GET ALL THE FLAVOR COMING
OUT OF THE BONES AND THE SKIN.
DELICIOUS.
TROPICAL RISOTTO.
I BROUGHT YOU WITH ME, CUBAN,
TO BE THE AUTHENTICATOR.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL?
THIS GOOD. LEGIT.
NICE JOB, CHEF.
THANK YOU.
YOU GOTTA COME BACK.
WE'RE HANGING OUT
IN QUEENS, NEW YORK,
TRYING SOME OFF-THE-HOOK
CUBAN FOOD AT RINCON CRI-YOLO.
DID I SAY IT RIGHT?
"CRIOLLO,"
LIKE A "YO-YO."
CRIOLLO.
♪♪
WELCOME BACK TO TRIPLE "D."
HERE WE ARE IN QUEENS, NEW YORK,
HANGING OUT
WITH MY BUDDY, CARL THE CUBAN,
AND, UH, IT'S CALLED...
RINCON CRIOLLO.
RINCON...
CRIOLLO.
"CRIOLLO"?
RINCON CRIOLLO.
I STILL CAN'T
GET IT RIGHT.
ARROZ CON POLLO.
IT'S VERY AUTHENTIC.
IT COMES FROM THE HEART.
RINCON CRIOLLO STEAK.
IT HAS THAT TRADITIONAL TASTE.
THE FLAVOR TAKES YOU BACK HOME.
THAT'S 'CAUSE
CUBAN-BORN OWNER RENÉ ACOSTA
AND HIS GREAT-NEPHEW RUDY...
PICADILLO.
ARE SETTING THE TABLE
WITH THE FLAVORS OF HAVANA.
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE
CUBAN FOOD?
SEASONED, NOT SPICY.
'CAUSE PEOPLE THINK,
"OH, CUBA, MEXICO..."
NO.
NOT EVEN CLOSE.
THAT SEASONED FLAVOR GETS
INTO AUTHENTIC CUBAN DISHES
LIKE PICADILLO, OXTAIL STEW,
AND THE HOUSE FAVORITE...
ROPA VIEJA.
I AM HAVING THE ROPA VIEJA,
WHICH IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S VERY TRADITIONAL CUBAN.
IF YOU KNOW CUBAN FOOD,
YOU KNOW ROPA VIEJA.
MEANS "OLD CLOTHES."
"OLD TORN CLOTHES."
ABSO--SHREDDED BEEF.
SO TELL ME
HOW WE DO IT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA PRESSURE-COOK
OUR FLANK STEAK.
FLANK STEAK'S GREAT
BECAUSE IT'S GOT GOOD FAT,
IT'S GOT GOOD, STRINGY,
TENDER MEAT...
AND IT'S EXCELLENT
FOR SHREDDING.
ANY SEASONING?
NO SEASON. NO SEASON.
ALL THE SPICE, EVERYTHING
GOES INTO THE SAUCE.
HOW MANY POUNDS?
THIS IS ABOUT 30 POUNDS.
AND YOU'LL GO
THROUGH THIS HOW FAST?
THIS LASTS ABOUT TWO DAYS.
(whistles)
IT IS THE HOUSE FAVORITE,
FOR SURE.
WE'RE GONNA SHRED IT...
GONNA SHRED IT.
BUT BEFORE WE DO THAT,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE SAUCE
THAT GOES
WITH THE ROPA VIEJA.
CORRECT.
SO WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GET A LITTLE OIL IN THERE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
THROW SOME ONIONS IN THERE.
(sizzling)
NOW THE GREEN BELL PEPPER,
WHICH IS COMPLETELY INDIGENOUS
TO THE CUBAN-STYLE FOOD.
CORRECT. GONNA GET
SOME GARLIC SAUCE IN THERE.
I LOVE THE GARLIC SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND PUT
HALF A BOTTLE OF WHITE WINE.
GO AHEAD AND PUT
THE PLUM TOMATOES IN THERE.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE
A GIGANTIC SOFRITO.
WE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND ADD OUR SPICES.
GROUND BAY LEAF,
WHITE PEPPER, OREGANO.
CUMIN, WE DO ADD A LITTLE BIT
MORE THAN EVERYTHING ELSE.
WE ADD OUR CHICKEN BASE,
BIG SCOOP.
FANTASTIC NEON YELLOW.
TOMATO PASTE.
BIG WITH THE TOMATO PASTE.
HOW MUCH ARE YOU
PUTTING IN HERE, DUDE?
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
(laughs)
YOU PUT A WHOLE NUMBER 10 CAN,
PRACTICALLY.
LAST IS OUR KETCHUP.
THIS GIVES IT
THAT NICE, SWEET TOUCH.
I'VE MADE A LOT OF CUBAN FOOD,
MY FRIEND.
I HAVE NEVER
PUT KETCHUP IN IT.
NEVER PUT KETCHUP IN IT.
LOT OF PEOPLE,
WHAT THEY DO IS THEY ADD SUGAR.
WE DON'T ADD ANY SUGAR.
THIS IS WHAT GIVES IT
THE NICE SWEETNESS.
HEY, NEXT TIME, HOW ABOUT
WE JUST CUT THE WHOLE LID OFF?
MY UNCLE DOESN'T WANT IT
THAT WAY. (laughs)
REALLY?
HE WANTS IT POURED IN
LITTLE BY LITTLE.
SO HOW LONG'S THIS
GONNA COOK LIKE THIS?
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND LET THIS SIMMER
FOR ABOUT A GOOD 20 MINUTES.
AND THEN THIS IS
THE ROPA VIEJA SAUCE.
WE'LL SHRED THE MEAT
AND THEN BRING IT ALL TOGETHER.
THAT'S IT.
GOT IT.
GET AWAY FROM THAT.
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND GET
THE BEEF READY TO BE SHREDDED.
AND THAT JUICE IS GONNA
GO IN THE SAUCE, TOO?
JUST MEAT STOCK HERE'S GONNA GO
RIGHT INTO THAT SAUCE, YEP.
OH, NICE.
AND I MEAN, WE'RE JUST TALKING
LITERALLY SHREDS APART,
AND THAT'S WHY
IT LOOKS LIKE OLD CLOTHES.
CORRECT.
THIS IS A PLETHORA.
DO THE MEAT JUICES
GO IN YET?
YEP.
NOW YOU GOT FAT AND EVERYTHING
GOING IN THIS. UH-HUH.
IT'S LIKE BEING RIGHT
AT THE RIM OF THE VOLCANO
IN FLAVOR TOWN, MAN.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
NOW HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA GO TOGETHER
BEFORE WE GET TO EAT IT?
GOOD 30 MINUTES.
FANTASTIC.
LET'S SEE IT, BROTHER.
OUR DELICIOUS ROPA VIEJA.
THAT'S A LOT OF VIEJA...
LOT OF ROPA.
MIX THESE WHITE RICE
AND BLACK BEANS TOGETHER.
OKAY. NOW WHAT?
OKAY, GET A SPOON OF WHITE RICE
AND BLACK BEANS IN THERE...
LIKE THIS?
AND FOLLOW IT UP
WITH A SCOOP OF ROPA VIEJA.
THAT'S A MOUTHFUL RIGHT THERE,
AND I DON'T MEAN
JUST BECAUSE OF THE AMOUNT.
I'M JUST TALKING ABOUT...
THE FLAVOR.
YOU GET THE CREAMINESS
OF THE BEANS
AND A LITTLE SALT
COMING FROM THAT RICE.
THEN YOU GET
THE TEXTURE OF THE MEAT.
HOW JUICY IT IS.
YEAH.
THE MEAT REALLY, REALLY
HOLDS ON TO THE SAUCE.
DELICIOUS. JUST TAKE IT
AWAY FROM ME, SERIOUSLY.
THANK YOU. (laughs)
(mouth full)
I'M OUTTA HERE.
(laughs)
GIVE ME THOSE BEANS, TOO.
THERE YOU GO. (laughs)
I'LL BE BACK.
(Rudy) ROPA VIEJA.
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST AROUND
IF YOU HAVE A MOMENT TO TRY IT.
IT'S NOT A MOMENT TO TRY IT.
IT'S A FOURTH STOMACH TO TRY IT,
IS MORE OF MY ISSUE.
OH.
MY MOM IS CUBAN,
AND IT'S KIND OF LIKE
BEING THERE, BUT IN QUEENS.
AND SO THIS IS NOT
JUST A RESTAURANT.
THIS IS A CULTURAL EXPERIENCE.
CORRECT.
FAMILY-OWNED, LOTS OF CHARACTER,
AND GREAT, SCRATCH-MADE FOOD.
EXCELLENT PLACE.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED TO
CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA...
SO MEAT, TAXIDERMY--
IT'S A THEME, RIGHT?
YEAH.
WHERE THE HEADS ON THE WALL
ARE NO MATCH...
(Guy) THAT'S A MONSTER.
FOR THE SANDWICHES
ON THE PLATE.
GONNA HAVE TO
RELEASE MY JAW.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
GO COBRA KAI ON THIS THING.
(chuckles)
♪♪
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY,
AT SOME POINT IN TIME
IN THEIR LIFE, WANTS TO BE IN
THE RESTAURANT AND BAR BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW, THEY GET
THAT IDEA IN THEIR MIND
OF THE PERFECT PLACE
THEY WANT TO HAVE,
AND SOME ACTUALLY
MAKE IT A REALITY,
LIKE THE JOINT
WE'RE ABOUT TO VISIT HERE
ON THE NECK OF THE PENINSULA
IN CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA.
THIS IS WHERE
JEN AND MIKE KULICK
ARE MAKING IT HAPPEN.
THIS IS THE TATTOOED MOOSE.
(Mike) ORDER UP.
PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
LUCKY #1 WITH SLAW.
THE SANDWICHES ARE SO UNIQUE
THAT I CAN'T WAIT
TO ORDER SOMETHING NEW
EVERY TIME I COME HERE.
HERE YOU GO, JEN.
CHICKEN SALAD B.L.T.
THIS PLACE HAS GOT THAT COLLEGE
FEEL. YOU CAN COME HERE TO PLAY.
I MEAN, THEY GIVE YOU SHARPIES
AND LET YOU GRAFFITI EVERYTHING.
REUBEN AND SLAW.
PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
(ding)
SO SOMEONE OPENS A JOINT
CALLED "TATTOOED MOOSE,"
I KNOW
YOU PROBABLY DUG IT.
IT'S GOOD BAR FOOD,
AND YOU CAN'T BEAT THIS.
JUST TRY TO AVOID EYE CONTACT
WITH THE STUFFED CRITTERS
STARING DOWN
AND FOCUS ON
THE PARTY ON YOUR PLATE.
IT'S LIKE GOING TO
MY DAD'S HUNTING LODGE,
BUT SOMEHOW THEY MAKE IT COOL.
YOU GOT A LUCKY #1?
THAT'S WHAT JEN AND MIKE KULICK
WERE GOING FOR
WHEN THEY OPENED THIS JOINT
BACK IN 2010.
SO MEAT, TAXIDERMY--
IT'S A THEME, RIGHT?
YEAH.
(laughs)
NICE.
WE DON'T REALLY CATER
TO VEGETARIANS.
DUCK CLUB. PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
THE DUCK CLUB IS TO DIE FOR.
THE DUCK WITH THE BACON
AND THE CHEESE--
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
ALL RIGHT.
EXPLAIN, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
UH, WE'RE MAKING
SOME DUCK CONFIT.
THERE'S A MOOSE HEAD AND A BUNCH
OF NEONS ON THE WALL.
YOU SURE
WE'RE DOING DUCK CONFIT?
WE'RE GONNA DO DUCK CONFIT.
HERE WE GO.
WE'RE GONNA BRINE THIS DUCK.
KOSHER SALT.
SALT HELPS TENDERIZE THE MEAT.
LITTLE BAY LEAF.
BAY LEAVES. STIR IT UP.
LET'S GET SOME DUCK LEGS
IN HERE. NOW FOR THE BRINE.
YEP.
LET IT GO FOR 24 HOURS.
WE DRAINED OFF THE SALTWATER.
ON WE GO.
PUT THE DUCK IN A ROASTING PAN.
A WHOLE BUNCH OF FRESH THYME.
DUCK FAT MAKES IT PERFECT.
NOW IS THIS YOUR DUCK FAT THAT
YOU'RE SAVING AFTER THIS HAPPENS
AND THAT YOU'RE--
THIS IS OUR DUCK FAT.
SO YOU'VE GOT THE DUCK
JUST ALL CRAMMED IN THERE.
REMEMBER THE WHOLE
CONFIT-ING IDEA.
WHEN WE PULL THIS OUT, THE DUCK
SHOULD BE JUST TO THE POINT
WHEN YOU START TO PULL ON IT,
IT STARTS TO SHRED.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
UH, YOU HAVE ME SO FAR.
OKAY.
THYME, DUCK, AND BRINE?
YOU HAVE THEIR ALBUM, DON'TCHA?
ALL OF 'EM.
IN THE OVEN. WHAT TEMP?
IN THE OVEN.
4 AND A QUARTER
FOR ABOUT 3 HOURS.
WHERE YOU BEEN?
COOKING DUCK.
(whispers) NICE.
(normal voice) SO IT'S
COOLED DOWN A LITTLE BIT?
WE LET IT COOL DOWN
JUST A LITTLE BIT
SO WE CAN HANDLE IT SAFELY.
WE SEPARATE OUT
THE SKIN, THE MEAT.
OH. THAT'S NICE.
WE GOT A LITTLE BIT OF THAT SALT
COMING THROUGH ON THAT DUCK.
MMM. NEXT STEP?
CRACKLINGS.
WE'RE GONNA FRY THE SKIN.
AND WE'RE GONNA CHOP THAT UP
AND MIX IT INTO THE DUCK MEAT?
MIX IT BACK IN
WITH THE MEAT.
DUCK CONFIT ON THE FLAT TOP,
COUPLE SLICES OF BACON.
LOCAL BREAD?
HAWAIIAN BREAD.
THREE GO ON THIS?
THAT'S A MONSTER.
IT'S A BIG SANDWICH. WE'RE GONNA
BUILD THIS THING UP LIKE A CLUB.
OUR DUCK AND OUR BACON.
OUR SMOKED CHEDDAR CHEESE--
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
MORE OOMPH.
OOF.
OKAY, WE'RE ALL SET.
PLENTY OF GARLIC AIOLI.
LETTUCE, TOMATO, AND ONION.
SALT AND PEPPER--
MAKE EVERYTHING DELICIOUS.
PICK IT. THERE'S THE BOTTOM
OF OUR SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THAT. (whistles)
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
LET'S GET AFTER IT.
MMM.
YOU SHOULD TRY THAT...
WHEN YOU MAKE YOUR OWN.
(laughs)
YOU HAVE TO HUNCH THIS ONE,
BUT THIS IS THE KEY THAT
WE HAVE NOT SEEN IN THE HUNCH--
AND I WANT TO
RUN THIS IN SLO-MO--
IS THAT WHEN
YOU GET IT HERE...
NOW YOU HAVE TO DO THE...
THE WIGGLE. YOU GOTTA--YOU GOTTA
DO THE--YOU GOTTA DO THE WORM.
LIKE THAT.
LET'S SEE IF I GOT IT.
(mumbles) SEE?
NOW WEDGE, WEDGE, WEDGE...
NICE!
GOOD JOB.
BUT I GOTTA TELL YOU...
THE DUCK IS TENDER,
THE BREAD PLAYS
INTO IT PERFECTLY,
NICE, BIG, FAT TOMATOES,
THE VEGGIES WORK IN,
THE GARLIC AIOLI--
I COULDN'T CHANGE A THING ON IT.
THIS IS MONEY, DUDE.
MMM. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
YOU UNDERSTAND ALL THAT?
YEAH. GOT IT.
(woman)
THE DUCK CLUB WITH FRIES.
AND, BOSS, WHAT ARE YOU HAVING
DOWN THERE? THE DUCK CONFIT?
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST SANDWICH
I'VE EVER EATEN.
ORDER UP.
BUT THIS MOOSE
AIN'T NO ONE-TRICK PONY.
FOLKS ARE ALSO CRAZY
ABOUT THE DUCK HASH,
THE GARLIC BLUE CHEESE FRIES,
AND IF YOU'RE FEELING LUCKY...
(Mike) LUCKY #1, SINGING.
PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
(bell dings)
THE LUCKY #1 IS A BRAISED
PORK BELLY WITH KIMCHI.
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING PORK BELLY.
WE'RE GONNA USE THIS
IN THE LUCKY #1.
BIG, FAT PORK BELLY.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA MIX UP A CURE.
OKAY.
KOSHER SALT,
GROUND BLACK PEPPER, PINK SALT.
WE'LL MIX THIS UP.
SEASON THIS UP NICELY.
SO NOW WE'VE GOT THIS RUBBED.
LET IT GO FOR A DAY.
GOOD MORNING.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
HIT IT.
(sizzling)
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS THING
RIGHT ON A FLAT TOP
AND MAKE IT NICE AND CRISPY.
KIND OF CRISPED UP THAT SKIN.
NOW INTO THE PAN.
CHOPPED ONIONS,
CELERY, BARBECUE SAUCE,
LITTLE LOUISIANA HOT SAUCE,
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
BRAISE IT FOR A FEW HOURS.
HOW MANY HOURS?
4 HOURS AT ABOUT 300 DEGREES.
THEN IT COOLS,
GETS CUT SUPER THICK,
AND HEADS TO THE FLAT TOP.
THAT'S A SLAB.
SO WE LET THAT GO, AND THEN
WE'LL BUILD THE SANDWICH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOT IT.
BUT WAIT. THERE'S MORE.
THE LUCKY #1 GETS TOPPED
WITH REAL-DEAL KIMCHI
THAT TAKES SEVEN DAYS
TO FERMENT.
TWO DAYS OUT IN THE KITCHEN,
AND THEN ANOTHER FIVE DAYS
IN THE WALK-IN.
WHEW. BACON'S DOWN.
TOASTY BUN, BUNCH OF
WASABI MAYONNAISE...
LITTLE WASABI MAYO. MMM.
CRISPY FRIED PORK BELLY,
FRESH TOMATO,
COUPLE SLICES OF CUCUMBER,
KIMCHI...
SEVEN-DAY KIMCHI.
CILANTRO.
NICE CALL.
LITTLE GREEN ONION,
CRISPY FRIED ONION TO GIVE IT
A LITTLE BIT MORE TEXTURE,
AND WE'LL HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE SWEET CHILI SAUCE.
CHILI SAUCE.
THIS THING'S SO HARD TO EAT.
♪ DUN-DUN ♪
♪ DUN-DUN DUN-DUN DUN-DUN ♪
HAVE TO RELEASE MY JAW.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO GO COBRA KAI
ON THIS THING.
(chuckles)
MMM.
(mumbles)
LET'S THIS BREAK THIS DOWN.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN BACON
FOR THIS...
AND YOU SERVE
THIS RIDICULOUS...
SLAB OF IT,
BUT ADDING THE CILANTRO,
THE CRISPY ONIONS,
THE HOMEMADE KIMCHI--
I MEAN, JUST ALL THE COMPONENTS,
MY FRIEND...
THAT'S ABOUT AS GOOD
AS YOU'LL FIND IT.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THE MOOSE IS LOOSE.
(woman) LUCKY #1 WITH SLAW.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
THE #1 IS DELICIOUS.
(woman) IT'S NOT TYPICAL THAT
YOU GET THIS MUCH PORK BELLY.
THE KIMCHI
IS FERMENTED PERFECTLY.
IT'S A GREAT LUNCH AND DINNER.
THE FOOD IS A LOT DIFFERENT
THAN I THINK "TATTOOED MOOSE"
MAY COME OFF TO SOMEBODY.
WE'D RATHER HAVE THEM
HAVE LOW EXPECTATIONS
AND THEN BE SURPRISED.
I MEAN... (laughs)
UNDER-PROMISE
AND OVER-DELIVER.
EXACTLY.
(all laugh)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED TO
"THE DRIVE" IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
WHERE A ROCKIN' BAR
IS SCRATCH-MAKING...
THAT IS ABOUT THE FASTEST
I'VE EVER SEEN IT.
SIGNATURE SAUSAGES.
GETTING ONE OF THOSE
FOR MY HOUSE.
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
ON COMMERCIAL DRIVE--
OR "THE DRIVE,"
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT--
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE TWO BUDDIES
ARE MAKING HOMEMADE SAUSAGE
AND SERVING COCKTAILS.
WELL, THE BUTCHER SHOP NEXT DOOR
DECIDES TO RETIRE,
SO THEY FIGURE, "HEY, LET'S BLOW
A HOLE THROUGH THE WALL,
"START MAKING MORE SAUSAGE,
SERVE IT IN THE RESTAURANT,
AND SELL IT FOR RETAIL."
IT'S A STORY YOU HEAR EVERY DAY.
THIS IS FALCONETTI'S.
♪♪
PLATING MY TWO CHICKEN THAIS.
ARE THERE A LOT OF
SAUSAGE JOINTS IN VANCOUVER?
NOT, LIKE, BARS
OR RESTAURANTS OR ANYTHING
THAT REALLY MAKE
THEIR OWN SAUSAGES.
THIS IS WHAT I'VE BEEN
LOOKING FOR, FOR A LONG TIME.
AND THE PLACE
WAS A LONG TIME COMING
FOR BUDDIES ED DOLMAT...
MUSSELS IN ABOUT FOUR MINUTES.
AND CARMINE FALCONE.
HERE YOU GO, GUYS.
MY DAD WAS A BUTCHER
FOR 40 YEARS,
NEXT DOOR, KIND OF
A STAPLE ON THE DRIVE.
HE WAS THE BUTCHER SHOP
NEXT DOOR?
ABSOLUTELY, YEAH. I USED TO
WORK THERE WHEN I WAS A KID.
AND WHEN CARMINE'S DAD RETIRED,
THEY TOOK THE BIZ...
TWO POLISH, TWO SIDES FRIES.
AND STARTED MAKING SAUSAGE
TO SERVE IN THE BAR.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT TYPES
OF SAUSAGE DO YOU MAKE?
UPWARDS ABOUT 15.
FROM FLAVORS LIKE
CAJUN CHORIZO...
THERE'S YOUR QUESADILLA
FOR YA.
STUFFED IN A QUESADILLA...
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELISH.
TO THE YUCATAN...
MMM.
A SPICY CHICKEN SAUSAGE
SERVED IN A TACO.
REALLY DELICIOUS
AND SPICY.
OR HOW ABOUT A CURRY SPICE
THAI CHICKEN SAUSAGE...
TWO CHICKEN THAIS READY.
SERVED THE OLD-SCHOOL WAY,
INSIDE A BUN?
I EAT IT ALL THE TIME.
ALL RIGHT. SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN. WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
CHICKEN THAI.
HERE'S OUR GROUND CHICKEN MEAT.
WOW--WITH THE SKIN.
LET'S SEE IT.
WHOLE COCONUT MILK
AND SOME WATER.
SALT, CURRY POWDER...
(whistles)
GARLIC, WHITE PEPPER,
CORIANDER, CHILI POWDER,
GROUND GINGER,
AND SOME LIME JUICE.
AND WE JUST
MASSAGE IT ALL IN.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S LIKE
A THERAPY SESSION.
GREAT.
NOW FILL THE HOPPER.
WE'VE SEEN THIS ENOUGH TIMES
ON TRIPLE "D."
IT DOESN'T EVER GET OLD,
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU GET
THE SUPER THUNDER PRESS.
GETTING ONE OF THOSE
FOR MY HOUSE.
AND WHAT KIND OF CASING
ARE WE GONNA USE?
HOG CASING. SLIDE THAT ON.
HERE WE GO.
AND THEN WE START
THE PROCESS OF STUFFING.
PARTY TIME. WHOA.
AND WE'RE DONE.
THAT IS ABOUT THE FASTEST
I'VE EVER SEEN IT.
WE'LL JUST START
MAKING LINKS.
AND THEN WE TAKE IT
TO THE KITCHEN AND COOK?
THAT'S RIGHT.
LET'S MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE
TO COOK A SAUSAGE ON HERE?
SIX TO EIGHT MINUTES.
COOK IT OFF BOTH SIDES.
TRY NOT TO PIERCE THE CASING.
THAT'S THE THING.
WHEN YOU'RE COOKING SAUSAGE
ON THE BARBECUE,
DON'T HIT IT WITH A KNIFE.
EVERY TIME YOU HEAR
THAT JUICE COMING OUT,
THAT'S FLAVOR
LEAVING THE BUILDING.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA
HIT IT WITH?
SESAME OIL. THROW SOME
ASIAN VEGGIES IN THERE.
BIT OF HOISIN.
STIR THAT AROUND.
YOU HAD THE BUN MADE TO FIT
THE CURVATURE OF THE SAUSAGE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S COOL.
THE OTHER WAY.
THERE WE GO.
YOU JUST PUT
A LITTLE TOAST ON THAT.
THERE'S OUR LITTLE
BOUNCE TEST.
YOU KNOW THE CASING'S
NICE AND TIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE BABY THE SAUSAGE IN THERE.
GET OUR VEGGIES IN THERE,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
DRESS IT A BIT.
MORE HOISIN, BIT OF HOT SAUCE,
OUR FAMOUS HOUSE SAUCE.
IT'S A SPECIAL MAYO
SOUR CREAM MIXTURE.
LOOK AT THAT. MMM.
YOU GET THAT CURRY
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
DEFINITELY WORKS WELL
WITH THE ACCOMPANIMENT,
WITH THE HOT SAUCE,
LITTLE SWEETNESS IN THE HOISIN.
I LIKE THE VEGGIE COMPONENT
INTO IT.
MMM. NICE LITTLE SNAP
TO THE SAUSAGE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD SAUSAGE.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING, MAN.
THANKS.
MMM.
♪♪
THERE YOU GO.
WAY TO GET RIGHT AFTER IT.
(woman) I THINK FALCONETTI'S
IS DEFINITELY UNIQUE.
WHAT KIND OF BAR DOESN'T
SELL THEIR OWN SAUSAGES?
EXA--I MEAN, YOU'RE MISSING IT
IF YOU'RE NOT SELLING
YOUR OWN SAUSAGES.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
SOMETHING'S MISSING.
I LIKE YOUR BUSINESS PLAN.
THANKS, GUYS.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(song ends, crowd cheers)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY!
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY!
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT WEEK
ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
YOU EVER THINK ABOUT BEING
A COUNTRY-WESTERN SINGER?
THOUGHT ABOUT IT. HAVEN'T HAD
ENOUGH BAD STUFF HAPPEN TO ME.
(laughs)