HEY THERE, I'M GUY FIERI
AND I'M ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy)
THIS TRIP...
THIS IS GONNA BE FUN.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
LONG-STANDING LEGACIES...
YOU WISH YOU WERE HERE
RIGHT NOW.
(Guy)
IN CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA.
I BET I GET EAT IT FASTER
THAN YOU CAN SLICE IT.
I BET YOU COULD.
(Guy)
A ROCK-N-ROLL INSPIRED JOINT...
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
GIVE IT A FLIP
ON SOME SOUTHERN CLASSICS.
MMM-MMM-MMM!
IN BROOKLYN, NEW YORK.
C'MON HERE, GUY,
I'M NOT GONNA GET YOU DIRTY.
THE CLASSIC CORNER DELI...
LIKE BUTTER AND THE GRAVY,
WHAT A GUY.
(Guy)
CRANKIN' UP THE NEW YORK HERO...
(chef)
NOBODY MAKES IT LIKE US.
SINCE 1922.
TAKE A BREATH,
AND THE REST OF IT.
AND IN ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND.
IRISH FOG...
(Guy)
AN IRISH PUB...
HOW'S IT GOIN', BOYS?
(Guy)
WHERE TWISTS ON TRADITIONS...
THIS IRISH SUSHI IS THE BOMB.
HAVE 'EM BELLYING UP TO THE BAR.
I COULD DRINK THIS
THROUGH A STRAW.
OH YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON "TRIPLE D."
♪
YOU KNOW,
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT WHEN I THINK ABOUT
"TRIPLE D" ON THE EAST COAST,
ESPECIALLY LIKE,
IN THE BROOKLYN AREA,
I THINK ABOUT THOSE OLD-SCHOOL
ITALIAN DELIS ON THE CORNER.
YOU KNOW,
THEY'VE BEEN THERE FOREVER,
THEY'RE LOVED BY GENERATIONS
OF LOCALS,
AND THEY'RE RUN
BY GENERATIONS OF FAMILIES.
LIKE THIS JOINT, DEFONTE'S
IN BROOKLYN SINCE 1922.
C'MON ON DOWN, STEP UP.
SAUSAGE AND PEPPERS RIGHT HERE.
YOU WANT A NEW YORK HERO,
DEFONTE'S IS THE PLACE
TO GET IT.
NICKY SPECIAL READY.
WE WAS RAISED
WITH THESE SANDWICHES.
YOU WERE RAISED
WITH THESE SANDWICHES?
RAISED WITH THESE SANDWICHES.
SO ARE THESE GUYS,
LARRY DEFONTE STARTED EARLY.
(Larry)
NOBODY MAKES IT LIKE US.
I WORKED HERE
WHEN I WAS 16 YEARS OLD.
(Guy)
AND THIS GUY, EVEN LONGER,
'CAUSE NICKY DEFONTE IS FAMILY.
YOUR GRANDFATHER
STARTED THIS IN 1922?
RIGHT.
WE SELL MOSTLY COLD CUTS
AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
SO YOUR DAD'S THE ONE
WHO TOOK IT A LITTLE BIT MORE
INTO THE RESTAURANT...
INTO HOT FOOD.
EVERYONE WANTS TO HAVE
THIS LITTLE ITALIAN DELI
ON THE CORNER
THAT YOUR MOM AND DAD
TOOK YOU TO WHEN YOU WERE A KID.
NOW YOU TAKE YOUR KIDS TOO.
EVERYTHING THEY HAVE
UP ON THAT MENU BOARD
IS DELICIOUS.
FRESH MOZZAREL.
LARRY MAKES THE MOZZAREL
EVERY DAY
SO YOU KNOW
THE MOZZAREL IS FRESH.
VERY FRESH BREAD,
HOT, SLICED MEATS.
AND YOU CAN FIND ALL OF THESE
ON THIS MONSTER.
THE STEAK... PIZZAIOLA.
PIZZAIOLA.
START WITH A NICE PIECE OF
CHUCK MEAT.
CHUCK HAS GOT
A FANTASTIC FLAVOR.
I MEAN, THIS IS NOT
THE MOST TENDER PIECE OF MEAT.
NO, BUT IT COMES OUT
LIKE BUTTER.
LIKE THE BUTTER, THE GRAVY,
WHAT A GUY.
WE'RE GONNA TRIM HER DOWN,
SLICE IT UP.
C'MON HERE, GUY,
I'M NOT GONNA GET YOUR DIRTY.
SO IT GETS POUNDED DOWN
SO YOU'RE BREAKIN'
THE CONNECTIVE TISSUE
SO IT'S MORE TENDER.
OKAY, STOP, LOOK,
THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
YOU WANT ME IT FOR YOU?
GET AWAY FROM ME.
MY MOM IS GONNA BE SO UPSET.
NOW WE START ON THE GRAVY?
YES, WE HAVE SOME GRAVY HERE.
HE SAYS GRAVY
AND HE MEANS...
SAUCE.
TO THE REST OF THE COUNTRY
TOMATO SAUCE.
HERE IN THIS AREA,
GRAVY IS SAUCE.
I CAN'T KEEP IT STRAIGHT.
SOME BAY LEAF, SALT,
NEXT IS THE GARLIC POWDER.
FORTIFYING THE GRAVY?
EXACTLY, JAZZIN' IT UP.
BASIL, SOME BUTTER.
SO THIS IS GRAVY GONE WILD?
EXACTLY RIGHT.
OKAY, LET'S PUT A COVER ON IT.
PERFECT FIT.
OKAY, NOW YOU WANT
TO BROWN THE MEAT.
A LITTLE OIL.
NOW DOWN
WITH THE POUNDED-OUT CHUCK.
I DON'T WANT TO GET
YOUR SHIRT DIRTY,
WATCH OUT, GUY.
YEAH, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR THE CONCERN.
WE BROWN IT UP
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT IT IN HERE.
I DON'T WANT THE BLOOD
FROM THE STEAK TO GO
INTO THE GRAVY.
THE USC MARCHING BAND CALLED,
THEY WANT ONE OF
THEIR CYMBALS BACK.
AND LET IT GO FOR HOW LONG?
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
IT'S JUST GONNA BE
STUPID TENDER.
YES, JUST COVER IT UP,
WE'RE GONNA GET
SOME FRESH MOZZAREL
AND BAKE IT IN THE OVEN.
YOU GUYS MAKE
THE FRESH MOZZAREL?
YES, LARRY'S GONNA MAKE IT.
LARRY THE MOZZARELLA GUY?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME MOZZAREL?
YES.
WATCH OUT,
DON'T GET ANYTHING ON HIM.
OKAY.
THIS IS AWESOME.
GUITAR, IT'S CALLED.
CURD?
YES.
THAT'S A HERD OF CURD.
CUT IT UP.
THIS IS LIKE, A 43-POUND CHUNK
THAT COMES IN.
42, 43.
HUT!
WAS THAT A HUT HUT IN THERE?
EVERYBODY'S A COMEDIAN
IN THIS JOINT.
SO THE WAY WE SEE CURDS
WHEN WE MAKE MOZZ IS
IT'S ALL BROKEN UP.
THIS IS JUST COMING
AS A GIGANTIC BOG.
YES.
PUT IT THROUGH THE GUITAR
SO IT CUTS EVENLY.
SO IT MELTS EVENLY, TOO.
NOW HOT WATER?
BOILING HOT WATER.
PUT SOME SALT IN THERE.
THAT'S THE FLAVOR.
SO YOU'RE TAKING THIS
AND WORKING IT.   ADD HOT WATER.
STRETCHING IT.
STRETCHING IT,
IT'S GOTTA HOOK ALL TOGETHER.
GET THAT ELASTICITY
THAT YOU LIKE OUT
OF THE MOZZ.
LOOK AT THAT.
KEEP WORKING IT,
SEE HOW IT'S GETTING SMOOTHER?
NOW I HAVE TO DUMP THIS WATER.
I HAD TO DUMP THAT WATER OUT
BECAUSE IT'LL KEEP COOKING
AND ALL THE MILK WILL COME OUT.
YOU GOTTA WORK IT FAST,
IT'S SMOOTH LIKE THAT.
WHEN IT STOPS TEARING
IS WHEN YOU'RE DONE?
YEAH, SEE, YOU GO LIKE THIS
AND YOU MAKE NICE BALLS.
JUST LOOK AT THIS.
AND THAT'S CALLED
FRESH MOZZAREL.
THAT'S PERFECT.
GORGEOUS.
AND WE SLICE IT
THIN AS POSSIBLE.
MMM, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SERVE
OTHER FOOD.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS JUST HAVE THIS.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
SUPER CREAMY,
AND THEN IT JUST
STARTS TO DISSOLVE.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING, MAN,
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
I'M OUT?
NO, YOU'RE IN, DON'T THINK
YOU'RE GOING ANYWHERE.
HE'S GOT THE CHEESE READY,
LET'S SEE IT.
OKAY, PUT THIS IN HERE.
I'LL CUT THE BREAD...
YOU WISH YOU WERE HERE
RIGHT NOW.
LIKE, TAG TEAM SANDWICH MAKING.
STEAK PIZZAIOLA ON TOP, NICE.
DON'T GIVE HIM TOO MUCH, LARRY,
HE MIGHT COME BACK.
GRATED CHEESE, NOW WE'LL PUT
THE MOZZAREL ON TOP.
WE BAKE IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
BRING IT, NICKY.
TOP IT OFF.
A LITTLE BIT
ON THE HOT SIDE?
TRY THIS PIECE.
OH GOD, THAT'S HOT.
LOOK AT THAT CHUCK,
IT JUST FALLS APART.
IT JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
MMM, MELTED MOZZ,
IT REALLY BUILDS
EVEN MORE TEXTURE.
THE BREAD'S OUTSTANDING, MMM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT.
(patron)
I DON'T KNOW OF ANY OTHER PLACE
THAT CAN EVEN COME CLOSE
TO THIS.
YOUR MOM COOK LIKE THIS AT HOME?
UH, NO, WE JUST COME HERE.
(Guy)
'CAUSE YOU CAN'T GET THIS
AT HOME.
HAM GABAGOOL --
ROASTED...
HO, HO, HO,
HAM, WHO, HUH?
HAM GABAGOOL.
(Guy)
I'M GONNA NEED A DICTIONARY.
I SAID I THOUGHT I KNEW 'EM ALL.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
WHICH ONE IS
THE NUMBER ONE
SELLING SANDWICH?
ROAST BEEF, EGG PLANT...
MOZZAREL.
THIS IS TURNING INTO TOO MUCH.
(Guy)
DEFONTE'S IS JUST THE KIND OF
SANDWICH SHOP YOU'D EXPECT
TO FIND IN BROOKLYN --
AN OLD-SCHOOL ITALIAN DELI
ON THE CORNER.
AND THEY'RE SPEAKING
MY KIND OF LANGUAGE.
ROAST BEEF, CORN BEEF,
ROAST PORK, VEAL CUTLET,
STEAK AND PEPPERS,
PEPPERS AND EGG WITH MOZZAREL,
CHICKEN CUTLET...
WHAT ARE YOU,
AN AUCTIONEER?
I GOT STEAK PIZZAIOLA,
YOU ALREADY HAD.
MEATBALLS, EGGPLANT PARMESAN.
TAKE A BREATH,
AND THE REST OF IT.
WE'VE GOT HAM, SWISS,
MUENSTER CHEESE, TURKEY,
PROVOLONE, AMERICAN SALAMI,
HAM GABAGOOL.
ROASTED...
HO, HO, HO,
HAM, WHO, HUH?
HAM GABAGOOL.
HAM GABAGO...
HOW DID YOU SAY THAT?
HAM GABAGOOL.
SO IT'S HAM AND TURKEY.
WE MAKE IT ALL.
OKAY, HOW MANY SANDWICHES
WILL YOU MAKE IN A DAY?
2, 300, 2 OR 3.
TWO OR TREE.
WHAT'S ONE OF THE NUMBER ONE
SELLING SANDWICHES?
ROAST BEEF, EGG PLANT,
MOZZAREL.
OH, THIS IS TURNING INTO
TOO MUCH.
READY?
PLEASE.
THIS GETS GRAVY?
YES.
DON'T TELL HIM
ABOUT THE GRAVY.
OH, RIGHT TO THE SLICER,
THE WHOLE THING.
SO WHEN SOMEBODY ORDERS THIS,
THEY GET IT SLICED FRESH.
YES, ALL THE TIME.
MMM... TENDER.
HERE'S THE EGGPLANT.
SO EGGPLANT'S BEEN SKINNED,
LIGHTLY BATTERED?
YES.
FRIED IN OLIVE OIL.
NOW WE'LL PUT
THE FRESH MOZZAREL
THAT LARRY MADE...
NICE.
SEE THESE GUYS,
THEY'RE TRAINED TECHNICIANS.
SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY, YOU'RE GONNA PUT
THE GRAVY ON IT.
YOU'RE LEARNING.
THAT'S IT, NATURAL...
NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA PUT
THE GRAVY GRAVY.
WHAT GRAVY GRAVY?
NO, THAT'S FOR THE ROAST BEEF.
DON'T CHANGE
THE GRAVY DEFINITION ON ME.
WHICH ONE'S GRAVY,
THAT ONE'S GRAVY
OR THAT ONE'S GRAVY?
THEY'RE BOTH GRAVY,
I THOUGHT YOU GOT IT BY NOW.
(Guy)
THIS IS HOW IT'S DONE.
YOU DO THE ROAST BEEF
EVERY MORNING?
YES.
I'D LOVE SOMETHING TO DIP IN
BUT I DON'T WANT TO GET
THE WRONG GRAVY.
YOU WANT TO DIP IT IN THERE?
SEE, THAT'S WHAT I LIKE.
OKAY, GIVE IT A LITTLE DIP
IN THE GRAVY,
IN THE NATURAL GRAVY...
WHAT'S THAT MEAN, GOOD?
OH MAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
RIDICULOUS,
RIDICULOUSLY GOOD.
THE MOZZ...
(Nicky and Larry)
MOZZAREL.
I'M SORRY, GUYS,
I JUST LOST A POINT.
I'M GONNA GET
MY BADGE TAKEN AWAY.
THE MOZZAREL GIVES
GREAT TEXTURE.
THE ROAST BEEF
HAS GOT GREAT FLAVOR
AND DIPPING IT IN THE GRAVY --
THE NATURAL GRAVY,
IS THE WAY TO GO.
I LOVE THAT LITTLE EXTRA FLAVOR
YOU GET FROM THE EGGPLANT,
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
(patron)
THE BEST ROAST BEEF,
IT'S ONE OF THE BEST SANDWICHES
IN TOWN, I LOVE IT.
IT'S PHENOMENAL TO HAVE A
NEIGHBORHOOD ESTABLISHMENT LIKE
THIS
THAT STILL SERVES GREAT FOOD,
AND ALWAYS WITH LAUGHS
AND A SMILE BEHIND THE COUNTER.
I MEAN, THAT'S PART OF
THE REASON WE COME HERE.
A LOT OF SMACK BEIN' TALKED.
YEAH.
YOU TWO, I DON'T CARE,
YOU GUYS COULD BE SERVING
RAMEN NOODLES IN A CUP,
I MEAN, THIS IS HYSTERICAL,
IT'S A FLOOR SHOW.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL,
THIS IS OLD-SCHOOL.
YOU GUYS ARE THE BOMB.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, BROTHER, SO MUCH.
NATURAL GRAVY, REGULAR GRAVY,
GET IT STRAIGHT.
MMM.
(Guy) UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED TO
CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA.
YOU REALLY FEEL
THAT'S ENOUGH PORK
FOR ME, SON?
(Guy)
FOR A JOINT THAT'S GETTIN'
ITS NAME FROM ROCK HISTORY...
AND THEN RIGHT THERE
IN YOUR FACE...
(Guy)
AND IT'S FOOD
FROM SOUTHERN SOUL.
OH MY GOD,
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
YOU KNOW, I THINK EVERYBODY
IN FLAVOR TOWN KNOWS
THAT I'M A ROCKER.
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT ROCK-N-ROLL,
THE GREATS.
SO WHEN I FIND OUT
THAT THERE'S A RESTAURANT
IN THE WEST ASHLEY NEIGHBORHOOD
OF CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA
THAT GETS ITS NAME
FROM GET THIS,
THE BEATLES' "WHITE" ALBUM?
WELL YOU KNOW
I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS THE GLASS ONION.
(server)
HERE YOU GO,
THE SHRIMP AND GRITS.
WHAT MAKES THE FOOD HERE
REALLY GOOD IS THE LOCAL,
FRESH INGREDIENTS.
THE TOMATOES
DON'T COME FROM CALIFORNIA,
THEY COME FROM UP THE ROAD.
YOU CAN SEE
FOOD BROUGHT IN HERE.
IT DOESN'T COME IN FROZEN,
IT COMES IN FRESH.
SARAH AND CHRIS
MAKE MAGIC HAPPEN DAILY.
(Guy)
JUST A LITTLE HOCUS POCUS
COURTESY OF SARAH O' KELLEY
AND CHRIS STEWART...
SHRIMP BOY
AND A PORK LOIN PO BOY.
(Guy)
TWO FINE-DINING VETERANS
BRINGING HIGH-END FOOD
TO EVERYDAY PEOPLE...
IT'S THREE OR FOUR STAR DINING
AT ONE STAR PRICES.
WE THOUGHT WE COULD APPLY
THE SKILLS THAT WE HAD USED
IN FINE DINING
TO CREATE JUST A FUNKY,
CASUAL ENVIRONMENT.
(Guy)
BUILT AROUND THE TYPE OF COOKING
THEY GREW UP ON.
IT'S OUR VISION OF
SOUTHERN FOOD
INSPIRED BY
THE LOCAL INGREDIENTS.
(Guy)
LIKE THIS SOUTHERN STAPLE...
THE CRISPY CHICKEN LEG.
(Guy)
DONE A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
IT'S CONFIT, MMM.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
WE CALL THIS
THE CRISPY CHICKEN LEG.
CRISPY AS IF IT WERE FRIED,
BUT IT'S CONFIT.
OKAY.
I'M JUST GONNA POP THAT OUT
AND TAKE THAT OFF.
MAKIN' IT LOOK EASY, ISN'T HE,
OKAY, NEXT UP.
(Chris)
WHAT I WANT TO DO
IS I WANT TO CURE THESE
SO WE CAN GET THAT CRISPINESS.
AND WHAT KIND OF CRISPY
ARE WE TALKIN' ABOUT?
WE'RE TALKIN' CRISPY.
FRIED CHICKEN CRISPY
WITHOUT THE BATTER?
YEAH, THAT'S BASICALLY
WHAT WE'RE GOING FOR.
SALT, A LITTLE WHITE PEPPER,
A FEW SPRIGS OF THYME.
THAT'S JUST GONNA START SUCKIN'
THAT MOISTURE OUT.
RIGHT.
AT THIS POINT
WE'VE GOT OUR CURE,
WE'VE GOT SOME EXTRA FLAVOR
GOING ON WITH THE THYME
AND THIS WHITE PEPPER
AND EVERYTHING.
I'LL PUT THIS UN-COVERED
IN THE FRIDGE OVERNIGHT.
SO WE HAVE OUR NICE,
DRIED-OUT LEGS.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME WATER,
RINSE OFF THE EXCESS.
EXCESS SALT.
SHAKE 'EM OUT, SHINGLE,
IT'S ALL ABOUT BEING FLAT.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE THIS FLAT,
LIKE IF THAT'S CURLED UNDER...
YEAH, IMAGINE WHAT WOULD HAPPEN?
WE'LL JUST THROW A COUPLE OF
CLOVES OF GARLIC IN THERE
AND VEGETABLE OIL.
CAREFUL NOT TO UPSET
YOUR BEAUTIFUL SHINGLING.
SHINGLING.
GO RIGHT OVER THE TOP,
JUST COVER.
COVER WITH SOME FOIL.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS
AND WE'RE GONNA GO IN
A 350 DEGREE OVEN
FOR PROBABLY THREE,
MAYBE FOUR HOURS.
(Guy)
WE ARE LOOKING FOR THIS
TO GET CONFIT IN THE SENSE...
I MEAN, IT'S GONNA BE
ALMOST SHREDABLE?
IT WILL BE VERY SHREDABLE.
THIS IS COMPLETELY FINE.
GENTLY LIFT,
PAT THIS DRY A LITTLE BIT
BECAUSE I'M GONNA SEASON IT
A LITTLE BIT, SALT AND PEPPER.
HOT PAN, GENTLY LAY THAT
IN THE HOT PAN,
TURN THE FIRE BACK ON
AND GET IT NICE
AND CRISPY.
SO IT'S COOKED
ALL THE WAY THROUGH,
NOW WE'LL JUST PUT
A CRISP ON THE SKIN.
YOU'VE RENDERED DOWN
A LOT OF THE FAT
THAT'S IN THERE.
ONCE IT CRISPS UP,
WE SERVE IT UP.
YEP.
NICE, GOLDEN,
MASHED POTATOES,
A LITTLE COLLARD GREENS.
I AM A COLLARD GREEN MACHINE.
WE SERVE THE CRISPY CHICKEN LEG
WITH A LITTLE
SWEET PEPPER RELISH.
BEAUTIFUL.
PRETTY EASY TO EAT
WITH JUST THAT ONE,
LITTLE BONE IN THERE.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS,
OH MY GOD.
I WANT YOU TO THINK
ABOUT FRIED CHICKEN
REALLY COOKED THE RIGHT WAY
WITHOUT A BUNCH OF BATTER.
IT'S NICE AND TENDER
AND JUST PULLS APART
AND THEN YOU GET
THE CRISPINESS OF THE SKIN.
AND THEN
RIGHT THERE IN YOUR FACE
IS THIS RED PEPPER RELISH.
THE CONTRAST IS OUTSTANDING,
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
MMM-MMM-MMM.
(server)
CRISPY CHICKEN LEG.
THANK YOU.
AND IT'S GOT THE RELISH ON TOP
WHICH IS JUST A LITTLE SWEET
AND JUST A LITTLE PICKLY
AND IT IS FANTASTIC.
THEY DO SUCH A BEAUTIFUL JOB,
LITERALLY, EVERYTHING HERE.
(Guy)
FROM A RED VELVET CAKE
TO A REAL-DEAL CREOLE CLASSIC...
PORK LOIN PO BOY.
(Guy)
A NEW ORLEANS' SANDWICH
STUFFED WITH SMOKED PORK.
NOTHIN' SHORT OF DIVINE.
SMOKED PORK LOIN PO BOY,
SAY THAT FIVE TIMES FAST.
ALL RIGHT...
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE A PORK LOIN.
I DIDN'T SEE A SMOKER.
WE DON'T HAVE A SMOKER.
WE IMPROV, IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A SMOKED ROAST.
SO WE'RE GOING TO START
WITH THE BRINE.
WE'VE GOT TWO GALLONS OF WATER,
FRESH THYME, SOME BAY LEAF,
CRUSHED CHILI FLAKE,
SOME GARLIC, FENNEL SEED --
FENNEL AND PORK GO HAND IN HAND.
SOME SUGAR, SALT,
AND PEPPERCORNS.
WE JUST BRING THAT UP,
LET THE FLAVORS COME TOGETHER,
COOL IT DOWN
AND DROP THE PORK IN.
HOW LONG ARE WE LOOKIN' FOR?
NO MORE THAN TWO DAYS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SMOKE IT?
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SMOKE IT.
OKAY, LET ME SEE
THIS CONTRAPTION.
WHAT I DO IS TAKE HICKORY
BECAUSE IT TASTES THE BEST.
WE JUST PUT THE CHIPS
RIGHT ON TIN FOIL
DOWN HERE.
WE GO FULL BLAST WITH THE FLAME
FROM BELOW, BLOW TORCH...
THIS IS GONNA BE FUN.
GET 'EM BURNIN', GET US
A LITTLE CAMPFIRE GOIN' ON HERE.
SO YOU'RE GONNA PERFUME IT,
YOU'RE NOT SMOKIN' IT
SMOKIN' IT,
YOU'RE PUTTIN'
THE SMOKE ON IT.
RIGHT.
ONCE WE GET
THAT GOING PRETTY GOOD,
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE FIRE OUT.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA SMOKE.
SO I'VE GOT THIS LITTLE RACK
THAT I PUT ON HERE,
THEN WE'RE GONNA COME
INTO THE BRINE...
FISH OUT THAT PORK LOIN.
LAY IT DOWN
AND CUT IT IN HALF...
SO THAT IT FITS
IN THERE NICELY?
YEAH.
LAY THAT IN THERE,
LOOK AT THAT SMOKE
COMIN' UP REAL GOOD NOW.
WE'RE GONNA COVER IT.
SO 15 MINUTES LIKE THIS,
425 DEGREE OVEN FOR
ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
(Chris)
PULL IT OUT,
COOL IT DOWN.
(Guy)
SO WE'VE GOT
OUR SMOKED PORK LOIN,
NOW SLICE IT THIN,
FAT AND ALL?
FAT AND ALL, OH YEAH.
LOOK AT THIS.
I BET YOU I CAN EAT 'EM
FASTER THAN YOU CAN SLICE 'EM.
I BET YOU COULD.
WE USE LEIDENHEIMER BREAD
BECAUSE IT'S THE BEST.
TO KEEP IT AUTHENTIC
WE STILL CUT THE ENDS OFF.
THE ENDS OFF.
A LITTLE CLARIFIED BUTTER.
CLARIFIED BUTTER'S GONNA GO ON.
I'M GOING TO TOAST THIS
REAL QUICK.
WE'VE GOT WHAT WE CALL CREOLE,
IT'S CREOLE MUSTARD
AND MAYONNAISE.
OKAY.
THEN WE MAKE
THESE BREAD-AND-BUTTER PICKLES,
WHICH ARE DELICIOUS
AND WE JUST PUREE 'EM
AND MAKE A PICKLE RELISH.
THEN THE DELICIOUS PORK.
YOU REALLY FEEL
THAT'S ENOUGH PORK FOR ME, SON?
(laughing)
SOME TOMATOES,
SALT, PEPPER, THIS LETTUCE,
AND IT'S A FINISHED SANDWICH.
LOOK AT THAT, HMM?
THERE'S NOTHING ABOUT THAT,
THAT I'D KICK OFF THE PLATE.
LOVE THE PICKLE RELISH,
GETTING THAT ACID.
THE CREOLE, NICE AND CREAMY,
IT WOULD BE A GOOD MUSTARD.
AND THEN YOU'VE GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE
ON THE PORK,
BUT THE PORK IS SUPER TENDER
AND THERE'S A LOT OF MOISTURE,
THERE'S A LOT OF FLAVOR
INSIDE OF IT, THIS IS DYNAMITE.
PORK BOY,
READY TO GO.
WHATEVER CHRIS DOES IN THE BACK
MAKES THE PORK RIGHT.
THE FOOD IS DELICIOUS
AND THE PRICES ARE RIGHT.
YOU'VE GOT ALL KINDS OF FOLKS
THAT LOVE YA.
KEEP GOIN', KEEP DOIN' IT.
THERE'S NO GLASS CEILING
ON THIS GLASS ONION.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
OH, LOOK AT THAT MAGIC TRICK.
(Guy)
WE'RE HEADIN'
TO ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND,
WHERE AN IRISH PUB...
ANYTHING WRAPPED IN CABBAGE
IS A WIN.
(Guy)
IS GOING REAL DEAL
WITH THE GRUB.
OH MAN.
HERE WE ARE
IN ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND.
THIS IS THE HISTORIC DISTRICT.
TO ME, IT'S ALL
THE HISTORIC DISTRICT,
I MEAN, IT'S AMAZING.
AND WE'RE ON MARYLAND AVENUE
BETWEEN THE NAVAL ACADEMY
AND THE STATE HOUSE --
WHICH I THINK
IS UNDER RENOVATION,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT HAD
BEEN A GREEK RESTAURANT FOR 70
YEARS.
WELL THAT'S UNTIL
THREE IRISH DUDES
CRUISED INTO TOWN
AND SAY
THEY'RE GONNA MAKE A GO OF IT
AND THEY OPEN UP
GALWAY BAY IRISH PUB.
(Irish music playing)
CORN BEEF POPPER
IN THE WINDOW.
(patron)
IT'S JUST LIKE IN IRELAND.
(server)
WE HAVE A DUBLIN DIP SANDWICH.
AND THE FOOD'S
THE REAL DEAL.
IT'S SOLID.
THE SHEPHERD'S PIE,
THE FISH AND CHIPS,
IT'S A REAL TREAT.
A LOT OF IRISH JOINTS
IN THIS TOWN THAT
YOU'RE A FAN OF.
ONE, YOU'RE LEANING ON IT.
OH, GOOD.
(Guy)
AND THIS JOINT'S LEANING
ON THE TRUE IRISH ROOTS
OF OWNERS ANTHONY CLARK
AND FINTON GALWAY.
IS THERE A BAY
CALLED GALWAY BAY?
THERE IS.
THAT'S JUST A COINCIDENCE,
I DON'T KNOW WHY THEY
NAMED IT AFTER US.
WE CAN'T FIGURE IT OUT,
BUT WHAT THE HELL.
I LIKE THESE GUYS,
THEY RUN WITH THAT
IRISH MOXEY.
(Guy)
BUT THERE'S MORE THAN
IRISH ACCENTS KEEPING
THIS PLACE LEGIT.
DROPPING ONE ORDER OF
FISH AND CHIPS.
(Guy)
MEET CLASSICALLY TRAINED CHEF
MIKE MARONE.
I LIKE TO PUT A LITTLE BIT OF ME
IN AS MUCH OF THIS MENU
AS I CAN
AND NOT STICK
WITH A STRAIGHT IRISH.
(Guy)
SO SURE MIKE'S DOING
THE IRISH CLASSIC, CORN BEEF.
IT'S THE CHUNKED CORN BEEF,
THAT TEXTURE IS KILLER,
IT'S AMAZING.
(Guy)
BUT HE'S STUFFING IT
INTO CABBAGE ROLLS
AND MAKING WHAT I'D CALL
IRISH SUSHI.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
THE STUFFED CABBAGE?
THEY'RE GREAT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THIS IS ALL THE SPICES
FOR THE PICKLING SPICE
FOR OUR CORN BEEF.
(Guy whistling)
LIKE THE CORNUCOPIA OF SPICES.
AND WHAT'S THIS FOR?
THIS IS FOR THE CABBAGE WRAP.
ALL RIGHT,
GET ROCK-N-ROLLING.
ALL RIGHT, WE START
WITH DEHYDRATED ONIONS,
CHILI POWDER, MUSTARD SEEDS,
BLACK PEPPER, WHITE PEPPER,
ALLSPICE, WHICH IS THE FLAVOR
FOR CORN BEEF.
THAT IS THE KICKER?
YES.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
A HEAD OF GARLIC.
OH, LOOK AT THAT MAGIC TRICK.
HEY, NOTHING UP MY SLEEVE.
A LITTLE CLOVES,
WHOLE PEPPERCORNS, BAY LEAVES,
CORIANDER, CRUSHED RED PEPPER...
SO YOU PUT ALL THIS TOGETHER,
HOW LONG WILL THIS RUB SIT ON
THE AH, OOH, UH, UH, EH, EH...
THE RUB DOESN'T ACTUALLY
GO ON THE CORN BEEF,
THE RUB GOES IN
THE BOILING WATER.
SO YOUR BRISKET COMES IN RAW?
IT COMES IN CORNED.
YOU'RE GOING TO FORTIFY IT
WITH MORE FLAVOR.
YES.
AND WITH SPICES ARE US,
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
COVERIN' IT BY A COUPLE
OF INCHES.
SO NOW ONTO THE STOVE
5 1/2 TO SIX HOURS?
YEP.
ALL RIGHT, YOU BETTER HURRY UP,
I'M STARVING.
SO COOKED, COOLED,
AND READY TO ROLL.
YEP.
THIS IS WHERE SCIENTIFICALLY
WE SHOULD JUMP IN AND JUST
CHECK IT.
MMM, I COULD DRINK THIS
THROUGH A STRAW.
YEAH.
AND I LIKE TO CUT
ALL MY PIECES THICK.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE THESE,
WHAT'S NEXT?
INSIDE OF THE CABBAGE WRAP.
TWO SPOONS OF THIS MUSTARD.
OOH, CAVIAR.
IRISH CAVIAR.
THIS IS A WHOLE MUSTARD SEED
THAT'S SOAKED IN GUINNESS.
WHERE DO YOU FIND THIS?
IT'S IMPORTED FROM IRELAND.
IT REALLY LOOKS LIKE CAVIAR.
YES, THE GUINNESS
SEEMS TO SOFTEN UP THE SEEDS.
MMM.
YOU CAN TASTE THE GUINNESS.
YES, YOU CAN.
THEN WE ADD THE MAYONNAISE,
A LITTLE SALT, A LITTLE PEPPER,
A BIT OF HEAVY CREAM.
OKAY, SO THIS GOES
IN THE CABBAGE ROLLS
AND IS SERVED
AS A DIPPING SAUCE?
YES.
MAKE IT HAPPEN.
WE'RE GONNA MIX
SOME PLAIN OL' MASHED POTATOES.
THEN I ADD ALL MY CORN BEEF,
PLENTY OF THIS MUSTARD SAUCE,
CAN'T HAVE TOO MUCH.
THEN AS A SURPRISE
I'M MASHIN' THIS UP.
TAKE SOME STEAMED,
CHOPPED CABBAGE LEAVES
AND TAKE SOME OF THE MIX,
NOT TOO MUCH.
GET IT TO SIZE IN THE MIDDLE
AND IT'S A SIMPLE BURRITO ROLL.
POP 'EM BACK
INTO THE STEAMER
FOR A LITTLE WHILE
AND SOFTEN UP THE CABBAGE.
IRISH FOG.
JUST LIKE THAT.
STILL NICE AND TENDER,
SERVE 'EM LIKE IRISH SUSHI.
MMM, THIS IRISH SUSHI
IS THE BOMB.
I LOVE THE CABBAGE,
CABBAGE ISN'T COOKED TOO FAR
TO WHERE IT'S FALLING APART.
YOU'VE GOT A GOOD AMOUNT OF
CORN BEEF IN THERE,
CREAMY POTATOES,
A NICE BITE OF
THE MUSTARD SAUCE.
ANYTHING WRAPPED
AND STUFFED IN CABBAGE,
IN MY OPINION, IS A WIN.
I WOULD ORDER THIS
IN A HEART BEAT.
VERY GOOD.
NICE JOB, IRISH SUSHI.
(server)
KILLARNEY CABBAGE WRAPS.
GREAT COMFORT FOOD.
I USE IT AS A DINNER ACTUALLY
A LOT OF THE TIME
EVEN THOUGH IT'S ON
THE APPETIZER MENU.
CALAMARI.
IT'S NOT YOUR TYPICAL BAR FOOD.
REUBEN.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD HERE?
YOU KNOW WHAT, THERE'S NO TV.
THAT'S FUNNY,
THERE ARE NO TVs IN THIS JOINT.
SO YOU'RE ALWAYS
TALKING TO PEOPLE.
HOW'S IT GOIN', BOYS?
MOST PEOPLE THINK OF
IRISH PUBS AS THE PUB,
THE CRAIC SIDE OF IT.
THE WHAT SIDE OF IT,
THE CRACK SIDE?
C-R-A-I-C IS THE IRISH WORD
FOR FUN.
REALLY, THE PUB'S PART OF IT
BUT THE FOOD REALLY HAS TO BE
THE MAIN STAY.
YEAH.
I DIG IT MAN.
NO, YOU CAN'T DRIVE THE CAR.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE
"TRIPLE D" JOINTS
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT WEEK
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
HANG ON A SECOND.
OUR PROUD OWNER...
(Nicky)
THAT'S ME RIGHT THERE.
YOU GUYS, MIND
I'M TAKEN THE PICTURE WITH?