HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
TALK TO ME.
WE'RE SHARING THE ROAD...
WHAT KIND OF A POSE
IS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW!
WITH SOME TIME-TESTED
TREASURES.
THIS IS THE TRIPLE "D"
TELESTRATOR.
OUTSIDE BALTIMORE, MARYLAND,
THE GAS STATION TAQUERIA...
TORTA DE POLLO.
MIXING REAL-DEAL MEXICAN...
SAY IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
WITH A PIGSKIN LEGEND.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE FOOTBALL.
EVERYTHING LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE FOOTBALL TO YOU.
(laughs) IT DOES.
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
POTATO AND CHEESE PIEROGIES!
THE CLASSIC NORDEAST JOINT...
I WEIGHED 3,000 POUNDS
WHEN I LIVED HERE.
CRANKING OUT POLKA
WITH PIEROGIES SINCE THE '50s.
AND IN PORTSMOUTH, VIRGINIA...
ONE REGULAR
FRIED CHICKEN DINNER.
A 70-YEAR-OLD
FRIED CHICKEN SHACK...
IT'S GONNA BE
SOME GOOD FRIED CHICKEN.
STAYING TRUE
TO WHAT GOT 'EM THERE.
YOU GUYS DELIVER
TO CALIFORNIA?
FOR YOU, YEAH. (laughs)
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN ELKRIDGE, MARYLAND,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF BALTIMORE,
GETTING A LITTLE FUEL
FOR THE '68
AND A LITTLE FUEL
FOR THE GUID.
NOW THE CRAZY THING IS,
WHEN YOU'RE DOING
A TRIPLE "D" ROAD TRIP,
YOU PULL INTO A PLACE LIKE THIS
AND FIND OUT
THAT THEY'VE GOT THE BOMB
TAQUERIA RIGHT NEXT DOOR.
THE OTHER CRAZY THING
IS YOU HAVE YOUR BUDDY JOE.
HEY, JOE!
WHAT?
JOE THEISMANN, THAT IS.
YOU LIKE TACOS?
ABSOLUTELY.
CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS R & R TAQUERIA.
FOUR CHICKEN TACOS.
(woman) IT'S THE HIDDEN JEWEL.
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW IT WAS HERE,
BUT WHEN YOU FIND IT,
IT'S DEFINITELY WORTH IT.
FRIED TILAPIA.
HAVE YOU GUYS
BEEN HERE BEFORE?
OF COURSE.
AND THIS IS WHERE YOU
BRING HER FOR A DATE...
(laughter)
IS BACK HERE IN THE CORNER
OF A GAS STATION?
EVERY TIME IS EXCELLENT.
(man)
RODRIGO IS FROM MEXICO,
AND I THINK HE BRINGS
WHAT HE LEARNED
GROWING UP IN HIS MOTHER'S
KITCHEN TO THE RESTAURANT.
MUST HAVE BEEN A RIGHTEOUS
PLACE TO GET COOKING SKILLS,
'CAUSE RODRIGO ALBARRAN-TORRES
USED THEM TO PAY
FOR FLIGHT SCHOOL,
BEFORE LANDING BACK
IN THE RESTAURANT BIZ IN 2009.
TORTA DE POLLO.
HERE'S THE PLAY--
I'VE GOT TWO QUARTERBACKS.
ONE, A SUPER BOWL CHAMP
IN JOE, WHO LIVES NEARBY,
THE OTHER,
A SUPER CHEF IN RODRIGO.
IT'S GAME ON.
(sizzles)
WHAT WAS SO ATTRACTIVE ABOUT
BEING RIGHT IN A GAS STATION?
I OPENED THIS PLACE.
I STARTED THINKING ABOUT PUTTING
AUTHENTIC MEXICAN FOOD,
AND I REALIZED THAT
IT'S NOT THE LOCATION.
IT'S REALLY THE FOOD.
IT CAN BE REAL DEAL,
ALTHOUGH IT'S NOT
TABLES AND CHAIRS.
CORRECT.
GUARACHE AL PASTOR.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING FIRST?
SO WE'RE GONNA WORK ON
THE AL PASTOR.
IT'S THE PORK BUTT.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT, PORK BUTT?
I KNOW PORK BUTT. THAT'S
MY MIDDLE NAME IS PORK BUTT.
(laughter)
YOU'LL NOTICE
THERE'S TWO CHEEKS.
YES.
SO THAT WORKS OUT VERY WELL.
STOP. YOU'RE GONNA GET ME
KICKED OFF THE NETWORK.
GONNA SLICE IT FIRST.
START IT OUT THIN.
BUT I DON'T HAVE A TELESTRATOR
WITH ME, OKAY?
I GOT A PEN. I GOT A PLATE.
NOW WHAT HE DOES IS HE TAKES IT
AND SLICES IT JUST A LITTLE BIT,
THEN GRABS IT, PEELS IT OFF.
WHAT YOU DO IS YOU GET
A NICE, EVEN CUT LIKE THAT.
THIS IS THE TRIPLE "D"
TELESTRATOR.
GUAJILLO CHILIS.
MY FAVORITE CHILI.
YEAH.
DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER.
THIS IS
FOR THE PASTOR SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THESE,
BREAK 'EM DOWN,
TAKE THE STEMS
AND THE SEEDS OFF OF THEM,
LET THIS STEEP
IN THE WARM WATER,
THEN INTO THE BLENDER
WITH ALL THE INGREDIENTS?
YES.
GOT IT.
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT OREGANO.
MEXICAN OREGANO.
THYME LEAVES.
YOU'RE GETTING IN HIS WAY.
GARLIC.
I'M--I'M HELPING.
I'M AN ASSISTANT.
PINEAPPLE. PEPPER.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
THE PINEAPPLE.
THE ENZYME OF THE PINEAPPLE
HELPS IN THE MARINATING PROCESS.
CINNAMON.
A LITTLE CINNAMON.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE TAKING
THE GUAJILLOS
AND THE CHILI DE ARBOL.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM
IN THE BLENDER.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT PEPPER WATER.
YOU GOTTA SAVE THAT.
AND THIS ISN'T SUPER SPICY.
IT'S A VERY--
NOT SPICY.
IT'S VERY FLAVORFUL.
(whirring)
THEN WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MIX IT UP--
ALL THE PORK, THE ONIONS.
HOW LONG
DOES IT MARINATE?
WE USUALLY MARINATE IT
FOR A DAY.
OH, YOU KNOW IT'S GONNA
HAVE SOME GOOD FLAVOR.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
MM-HMM.
RODRIGO, WHAT ARE WE
DOIN', CHEF?
RIGHT NOW WE'RE DOING,
UH, GUARACHE.
GUARACHE! MEANS LIKE
FLIP-FLOP, MEANS LIKE SANDAL?
A SANDAL.
GIVE US A RUNDOWN.
CORN FLOUR.
MASA.
MASA. AND A LITTLE BIT
OF WATER.
NOW YOU MIX THIS
WITH YOUR FEET, JOE.
AND A LITTLE SALT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
YOU WANT TO GET THIS
JUST TO THE RIGHT POINT.
IT'S NICE AND LIGHT
AND FLUFFY.
YES.
REFRIED BEANS.
MAKE A CUP. FILL IT.
THAT'S--
FOLD IT.
THAT LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE FOOTBALL.
EVERYTHING LOOKS LIKE
A LITTLE FOOTBALL TO YOU.
(laughs) IT DOES.
NOW YOU JUST ROLL THIS OUT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA COOK THIS
ON THE FLATTOP WHILE WE COOK
THE AL PASTOR?
CORRECT.
LOOK AT THOSE GUARACHES,
MAN!
OAXACA CHEESE. AND THIS CHEESE
RIGHT HERE COMES IN A BALL.
AND YOU PEEL IT OFF.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE MOZZARELLA.
AL PASTOR.
OKAY.
A LITTLE PARM CHEESE.
PARMESAN?
IN MEXICAN FOOD?
YEAH. (laughs)
OKAY.
JALAPEÑO SAUCE.
SOUR CREAM.
NOW YOU GOT YOUR RED SAUCE.
AND AVOCADO.
THE KEY IS,
YOU'VE GOTTA SEASON IT
CORRECTLY, COOK IT CORRECTLY.
IT'S GONNA HAVE THAT
CHAR TO IT,
SO COOKING IT ON THE FLATTOP
IS CRITICAL.
THE MEAT IS TENDER ENOUGH.
IT'S NOT OVERCOOKED.
YOU TASTE THE CHEESE.
THE AVOCADO GIVES IT
A NICE FRESHNESS.
THE SALSA GIVES YOU
THAT LITTLE BIT OF...
(sniffles) MY NOSE IS RUNNING.
LISTEN. YEP.
WHAT YOU JUST HEARD
IS GUY FIERI'S CAREER ENDING.
THERE'S NOT TOO MUCH
OF ANY ONE THING.
(mouth full) I MEAN, THIS IS
THE REAL DEAL. I'M SERIOUS.
AND I EAT A LOT OF MEXICAN FOOD.
OUTSTANDING.
ANY RESTAURANT
THAT CAN GET BY
WHERE THERE'S NO PLACE
TO SIT DOWN, REALLY--
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE FOOD.
OH, YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
OH, YEAH.
(Rodrigo)
TACOS, ENCHILADOS.
GUY, JOE!
(Joe) WHAT?
WE'RE COMIN', WE'RE COMIN'!
YOU WANT A LAMB TACO,
HE MAKES YOU DO THE WORK
AROUND HERE.
HAVE US RUNNING AROUND.
COME ON, JOE.
OF COURSE I GOTTA ALWAYS
GET THE BACK END.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
RODRIGO,
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
WE'RE ABOUT TO DO
SOME LAMB TACOS.
WE'RE GONNA CHOP IT UP
AND ROAST THE WHOLE THING.
(Joe) NO PROCESSED STUFF HERE.
SO YOU GOT THE LAMB
BROKEN DOWN.
SO DO YOU HAVE A CERTAIN WAY
THAT YOU STACK THIS IN HERE?
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE
THIS MEAT IS EXPOSED SO--
AND MAKE SURE IT'S COOKED.
NEXT?
PUTTING THE--
THE VEGETABLES.
SO YOU GOT SOME ONIONS
AND SOME TOMATOES.
AND YOU USE A LITTLE BIT
OF BEAN PASTE.
BASICALLY WE'RE
BRAISING IT.
CORRECT.
(speaks indistinctly)
THIS IS THE REAL KEY.
NOW THESE YOU HAVE TO GET
SENT IN FROM MEXICO, RIGHT?
YES, THEY'RE FROM MEXICO.
AVOCADO TREE LEAVES.
YOU WON'T RECOGNIZE
THE FLAVOR SPECIFICALLY.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE A LEAF FROM AN ORANGE TREE
OR YOU'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO SMELL IT LIKE THAT,
BUT IT IS
REAL UNIQUE FLAVOR.
A LITTLE SALT?
A LITTLE SALT.
THESE BANANA LEAVES, MAN--
THIS IS THE WAY TO GO,
BECAUSE THEY'RE WAXY.
IT HOLDS THE MOISTURE,
AND THIS WAS YOUR PLASTIC WRAP
IN MEXICO.
I NEED THE FOIL.
WHAT TEMPERATURE ARE WE
GONNA COOK THIS OFF AT?
AT 450 DEGREES
FOR 4 TO 5 HOURS.
WE'RE GONNA GET
THE LAMB OUT.
YOU LOOKED AT ME
WHEN YOU SAID
TO GET THE LAMB OUT.
UH--
YES. YEAH.
HERE. GIVE ME THIS.
ARE YOU READY?
I GOTCHA. YOU DIDN'T HAVE
TO SAY ANYTHING MORE.
(laughing)
I JUST THOUGHT
THAT THIS WAS--
ME AND YOU, RODRIGO.
THIS IS MORE--
YOU'VE BEEN IN THIS.
(speaking indistinctly)
I MEAN, THIS IS YOUR--
WHAT--WHAT KIND
OF A POSE IS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW. I'M JUST
TRYING TO GET YOU DOWN.
WHAT IS THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU--YOU SHOW ME.
ARMS EXTENDED.
YES. OKAY.
A LITTLE BIT. NOT--
NOT WITH YOUR KNEES OUT.
YOUR KNEES HAVE TO GO
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
STRAIGHT AHEAD?
THERE IT IS.
I GOT IT. I GOT--
WHERE YOU GOING?
NO, WE GOTTA GET--
WE GOTTA GET THE HANDLE.
GET THE HANDLE.
I GOT FLIP-FLOPS.
THIS IS NOT GOOD.
HANG ON.
WATCH IT.
ALL RIGHT?
(speaks indistinctly)
HAVE YOU SEEN ANYTHING
MORE RIDICULOUS?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHAT DO YOU DO
WHEN WE'RE NOT HERE?
IT WAS A BIG LAMB.
IT'S A BIG LAMB.
IT IS A BIG LAMB.
ARE YOU READY?
THIS IS IT.
(exhales) LOOK AT THAT.
OH, MAN.
SEE, THE MEAT
JUST PULLS OFF.
PULLS RIGHT APART.
RIGHT APART.
YEAH.
SO--
OH, THE HUMMINGBIRD BITE.
SO WE GOT HERE PASILLA SAUCE.
NICE AND HOT.
SO PASILLA PEPPER.
ONIONS, GARLIC.
CINNAMON?
A LITTLE BIT OF CINNAMON.
OOH, YEAH.
RIGHT.
AND I DIP THE TORTILLA
A LITTLE BIT IN THE--
IN THE SAUCE.
PUT A LITTLE OF THE LAMB--
LAMB MEAT.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT.
THE NEXT ONE.
JOE, HE'S MAKING
YOURS SECOND.
YEAH.
PUT A LITTLE SAUCE.
OH... (chuckles)
SOUR CREAM.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
FIGHT ME FOR THIS ONE, BIG GUY.
RIGHT.
WHEN YOU GET THAT CINNAMON,
IT GIVES YOU
THAT NICE HOLIDAY
ROASTED LAMB FLAVOR.
YOU KNOW, WE USED TO--
THE CINNAMON'S VERY
PRONOUNCED IN IT, ISN'T IT?
(mouth full) I DON'T THINK
IT TAKES IT OVER AT ALL HERE...
NO, NO.
BUT IT ACCENTUATES IT.
THIS IS WHAT IT TASTED
LIKE WHEN YOU WERE A KID?
YES. JUST LIKE IT.
MMM!
I NEVER WOULD HAVE
LEFT MEXICO.
(laughs)
WRAP IT UP, JOE.
WE GOTTA GO.
DON'T BOTHER ME.
I'M EATING.
THEISMANN,
HANGING OUT WITH YOU
IS GONNA BE
BAD FOR MY FIGURE.
YOUR FIGURE?
RODRIGO, YOU'RE THE MAN.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
THIS IS CLASSIC NYE'S.
CAN'T DE-NYE'S IT.
FOR OLD-SCHOOL PIEROGIES...
SO WE HAVE GOT OURSELVES
A POLISH POT STICKER.
AND THE MOST DANGEROUS
POLKA BAND...
(cheering)
(chuckles) IN THE WORLD.
♪♪
LOTS OF FANS
HERE IN MINNEAPOLIS,
AND THAT'S INTERESTING,
BECAUSE THIS IS WHERE
THE CREW THAT BUILT TRIPLE "D"
CAME FROM.
NOW WHEN I COME TO MINNEAPOLIS
AND HANG OUT WITH THE TEAM,
THEY TAKE ME
ALL THESE CRAZY PLACES--
KRAMARCZUK'S.
GET FANTASTIC FOOD.
AND RIGHT DOWN THE WAY
WAS THIS PLACE
WHERE THEY HAD A PIANO BAR
AND POLKA.
THEN I FIND OUT
THEY'VE GOT THE BOMB FOOD.
I SAY, "WE GOTTA SHOOT
TRIPLE 'D' HERE!"
THIS IS NYE'S POLONAISE ROOM.
(polka music playing)
TRIPLE "D" CREW
BRINGS ME TO NYE'S.
THIS IS WHAT I WALK INTO.
AND THIS IS HOW THEY BEHAVE!
(cheering)
THIS IS NYE'S!
HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
LOOK--GOLD LAME.
GOLD LAME!
YOU JUST SAY "NYE'S,"
AND EVERYONE THAT'S
FROM MINNEAPOLIS KNOWS.
IF YOU HAVE FRIENDS
FROM OUT OF TOWN,
THIS IS A PLACE
THAT YOU BRING THEM
TO KIND OF GIVE YOU A TASTE
OF WHAT MINNEAPOLIS IS ABOUT.
I MEAN, THE WORLD'S MOST
DANGEROUS POLKA BAND? COME ON.
TOTAL PARTY ATMOSPHERE.
(man sings indistinctly)
(cheering)
(polka music resumes)
THREE DINING ROOMS, A FULL-BLOWN
BIG BAR, AND A LOUNGE?
RIGHT. WITH A BAR
IN EVERY ROOM.
WITH A BAR IN EVERY ROOM.
YOU GOTTA HAVE A BAR
IN EVERY ROOM.
'CAUSE YOU'RE IN MINNEAPOLIS.
WHERE NYE'S HAS BEEN
THE GO-TO JOINT SINCE 1950,
WHEN AL NYE GOT IT STARTED.
THAT'S THE GUY
WHO STARTED IT ALL.
PEOPLE LOVED HIM, TOO.
IT'S NOT JUST A REALLY
COOL BAR AND HANGOUT
WITH GREAT POLKA,
IT'S REAL-DEAL FOOD.
ABSOLUTELY.
THE PIEROGI HERE
WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
IT'S AMAZING.
IT HAS. CHANGED
MY WAISTBAND, TOO.
(laughs)
MADE BY THE PIEROGI MASTER
HIMSELF--
CHEF PAULY FOHRENKAMM.
THIS IS LIKE MY BROTHER
FROM THE NORDEAST.
GUESS WHO HE WAS
FOR HALLOWEEN.
THIS GUY. LITERALLY.
TAKE A LOOK
AT THE PICTURE.
I WON A, UH, HOUSE PARTY
COSTUME CONTEST.
ATTA BOY!
EVERYONE KNEW WHO I WAS.
WHICH PIEROGI
ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE MAKING POTATO
AND CHEESE.
MMM. TALK TO ME.
ALL RIGHT, PIEROGI DOUGH.
LET'S START IT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE STARTIN'
WITH SOME A.P. FLOUR.
(whistles)
OLIVE OIL. SOME WHOLE EGGS.
PINCH OF KOSHER SALT.
NOW WE'LL STIR THIS UP.
OKAY.
A LITTLE MORE WATER.
A LITTLE MORE WATER. OKAY.
LET IT REST.
WHAT ARE WE FILLING IT WITH?
MASHED POTATOES
AND FARMER'S CHEESE.
IT'S LIKE A COTTAGE CHEESE
WITHOUT THE CURDLE.
REAL NEUTRAL CHEESE.
COMPLEMENTS THE MASHED POTATOES
THAT WE USE.
OKAY. AND THE MASHED--
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
BUTTER. CREAM CHEESE
IS THE SECRET INGREDIENT.
THAT'S WHERE YOU'RE GONNA
GET YOUR SALT AND YOUR TANG.
SOUR CREAM,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
BLACK PEPPER,
WHITE PEPPER,
ONION POWDER,
KOSHER SALT...
AND A LITTLE MILK
TO MAKE CREAMY.
YEAH.
OKAY. HIT IT.
THAT MUCH CHEESE
GOES IN IT?
IT'S A ONE-TO-ONE.
NO WONDER I LOVE
THESE THINGS.
WE WHIP 'EM TILL THEY'RE
LIGHT AND AIRY.
(whirring)
TAKIN' OFF.
WORRIED.
OKAY.
THERE WE GO.
AND THAT'S GONNA BE
THE STUFF?
THAT IS.
DIG IT.
SO THE DOUGH'S HAD
A CHANCE TO REST.
NICE AND SILKY.
SO WE'RE PAN-SPRAYING
THE, UH, STAINLESS.
YOU KNOW, A LOT OF TIMES
YOU USE--
YOU'LL USE FLOUR
TO DO THIS.
YEAH.
THIS IS A LITTLE
UNORTHODOX.
TAKE THE REST OF THE DOUGH,
AND THEN WE ROLL
THIS BAD BOY OUT.
AND THIS IS HOW IT'S DONE
TO MAKE THOUSANDS OF...
YEAH.
PIEROGIES A, UH--A WEEK?
A WEEK.
HATE TO GET
IN TROUBLE HERE.
WANT YOU TO GO BACK
TO MAKING ME 550, LOUIE.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GET IT
TO, UH,
ABOUT 1/8 OF INCH OR SO.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE CUT
THESE GUYS OUT.
THAT'S IT?
TAKING LIKE A...
(speaks indistinctly) LIKE THAT.
IT'S THAT PRECISE
OF A PROGRAM HERE?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
ALL THESE YEARS THAT
I'VE BEEN LISTENING TO POLKA
I THOUGHT YOU HAD, LIKE,
SOME LITTLE PIEROGI MASTER
THAT WAS IN A ROBE.
AND WE'RE PULLING.
LIKE THAT.
FOLD.
AND THEN FORM.
SO WE HAVE GOT OURSELVES
A... POLISH POT STICKER.
THIS?
PERFECT.
SO NOW WE TAKE 'EM,
BOIL 'EM IN SALT WATER,
JUST TILL THEY FLOAT?
BASICALLY
TILL THEY FLOAT.
NOW THEY'RE COOLED.
NOW THEY GET FRIED.
BOOM.
SIX TO AN ORDER?
SIX TO AN ORDER.
ROUND 'EM UP.
THIS IS CLASSIC NYE'S.
CAN'T DE-NYE'S IT.
HERE WE GO! IT'S TIME!
THEY'RE UP! THEY'RE READY!
YOU SERVE 'EM WITH THE ONIONS
YOU JUST SAUTEED
AND THE SOUR CREAM.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA
HIT 'EM WITH SOME BUTTER?
OH, YEAH. EVERYTHING AT NYE'S
HAS BUTTER.
MMM! MMM.
THE ONION MAKES IT.
WHAT IS NOT TO LIKE THERE?
NICE, CRISP MIDWESTERN
BAR STAPLE RIGHT THERE, BABY.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
YOU GET RIGHT IN THERE
LIKE THAT.
MMM. I WEIGHED 3,000 POUNDS
WHEN I LIVED HERE.
EVERYTHING YOU WANT
IN A FOOD RIGHT THERE.
LOVELY AND BUTTERY AND TASTES
LIKE MY GRANDMA MADE THEM.
AND YOU CAN EAT 'EM
IN THE PIANO BAR
LISTENING TO SONGS
GRANDMA USED TO SING.
♪ SHINE ON, SHINE ON ♪
OH! THAT'S NOT GRANDMA.
THAT'S OUR FRIEND
THE BEAVER.
WOW.
♪ I AIN'T HAD NO LOVIN'
SINCE... ♪
♪ JANUARY, FEBRUARY,
JUNE, OR JULY ♪
(laughter)
I THINK I NEED TO FIND
A PRIME RIB SANDWICH
HEADLOCK.
THERE'S MORE COMING UP,
RIGHT?
YES.
WHOA!
WE'RE GOING
INTO THE FOOD COMA
AT NYE'S IN MINNEAPOLIS.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE BIT.
(whispers) SERIOUSLY,
TAKE IT EASY ON ME.
♪♪
HAD THIS IN THE TRUNK
OF MY CAR.
WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE AT NYE'S IN MINNEAPOLIS,
AND WE ARE MAKING
PRIME RIB.
(whispers) YEAH!
ANYTHING THAT THEY DO
WITH THE PRIME RIB HERE--
IF IT'S--IF IT'S THE SANDWICH,
IF IT'S IN THE PIEROGI,
IT'S JUST VERY, VERY TENDER
AND EXTREMELY FLAVORFUL.
I ALMOST CAME HERE
FOR THE PRIME RIB TONIGHT,
BUT I COULDN'T EAT THAT MUCH,
SO I GOT THE PRIME DIP SANDWICH
INSTEAD.
(laughing) IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A GREAT MEAT SANDWICH,
THIS IS THE ONE TO GO WITH.
A 109.
BONE IN.
OF THE BEST OF PRIME RIBS.
THE PREFERRED RIB,
BECAUSE OF THE FACT
THAT YOU GOT THE BONE--
FLAVOR--
BIG FAT CAP--FLAVOR.
AND THIS IS FOR
THE TUNA FISH SALAD SANDWICH.
NOT EXACTLY.
THANK YOU.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH SOME GARLIC.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
SERIOUSLY?
YEP.
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT
SNOW, 'CAUSE IT'S MINNEAPOLIS.
YOU'RE NOT SERIOUS.
WHAT, ARE WE SALT CURING IT,
MAKING JERKY FOR THE NORWEGIAN
TREK ACROSS THE GREAT LAKE?
ADDIN' FLAVOR.
NO!
THAT'S HOW WE DO IT.
IN ALL OF THAT SALT?
YEP.
I LIKE YOU.
ARE WE GONNA WRAP IT?
NO.
IT'S LIKE THAT--
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO
IN THE OVEN WITH IT?
YEP.
350.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT THREE HOURS.
DUDE! SALT CRUST
GONE WILD.
REMOVE THE FAT.
WHOA!
REMOVE THE BONES. COOL.
SO NOW IT'S COOLED DOWN.
WOW.
ALL RIGHT. THEN WE'RE
GONNA SLICE THIS GUY
FOR THE SANDWICH.
NICE MEDIUM RARE.
LOOK AT THIS. OH!
NOW THIS IS WHERE THAT
SALTY END WAS.
MMM! THAT FAT CAP HID IT
FROM ALL THAT SALT.
SOAKS RIGHT IN.
THAT IS SO TENDER. MMM!
HEAT THIS GUY UP
IN THE AU JUS.
GO, GO, GO!
LOOK AT THAT!
CULINARY OLYMPICS HERE.
AND IN THE MEAT CATEGORY...
AHH, MAN!
DO I GET ANYTHING ELSE
WITH IT?
AU JUS.
AU JUS IS GOOD.
YOU DON'T WANT
ANY OF THIS.
WE'RE ALWAYS ON THE QUEST
FOR THE GREAT DIP SANDWICH.
THE KEY IS THE BREAD
CANNOT GET IN THE WAY.
THE MEAT'S GOTTA BE
SUPER TENDER.
THE AU JUS CAN'T BE
TOO SALTY.
IT'S GOTTA BE A BALANCE,
AND IT'S GOTTA SOG UP NICE
AND HAVE NICE CRUMB
TO WHERE IT'S SUPER SOGGY
AND IT'S HOLDING IT TOGETHER,
IT'S NOT FALLING APART.
GOTTA BE
A BALANCED PORTFOLIO.
MY FRIEND, YOUR STOCK
HAS GONE THROUGH THE ROOF.
(playing polka music)
ALL THE GREAT PLACES
TO EAT IN MINNEAPOLIS,
AND YOU GUYS SHOW UP HERE
ON A DATE NIGHT.
IT'S REALLY THE PEOPLE,
AND IT GETS A VERY ECLECTIC
GROUP OF FOLKS.
FROM YOUNG TO OLD.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
THERE'S ALWAYS AN EXPERIENCE
OR A STORY A NYE'S.
THERE IS NO OTHER NYE'S.
THERE'S ONLY ONE.
SO MUCH FUN, AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO GET HERE AGAIN.
(polka music continues)
(man) ♪ IT WON'T BE LONG NOW ♪
(cheering)
♪ MY POLISH GIRLFRIEND ♪
♪ OUR NAME WILL BE THE SAME ♪
THAT'S WHAT YOU GOTTA
COME SEE AT NYE'S.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO PORTSMOUTH, VIRGINIA...
THIS THING IS GONNA BE
CRUNCHENTATIOUS.
WHERE A 70-YEAR-OLD
FRIED CHICKEN RECIPE...
SO THAT'S A WHOLE
HALF A CHICKEN?
LOOK AT THAT.
(laughter)
HAS 'EM STANDIN' UP FOR MORE.
YOU HAVE TO WAIT IN LINE?
OH, YEAH. FOR SURE.
"OH, YEAH.
DON'T BE DUMB ABOUT IT."
(laughter)
♪♪
I'M ABOUT 10 MILES WEST
OF NORFOLK, VIRGINIA,
OVER THE BERKLEY BRIDGE
IN A TOWN CALLED PORTSMOUTH
TO CHECK OUT--GET THIS--
A 71-YEAR-OLD FRIED CHICKEN
JOINT
WHERE THE THIRD GENERATION IS
TEACHING THE FOURTH GENERATION
HOW TO KEEP
THE FAMILY TRADITION ALIVE.
THIS IS MOSEBERTH'S CHICKEN.
HI. WELCOME TO MOSEBERTH'S.
WHAT CAN I GET FOR YOU TODAY?
ORDER UP.
REGULAR FRIED CHICKEN DINNER.
(man) I'VE BEEN COMIN' HERE
EVER SINCE I WAS SMALL.
GOT A LEG SPECIAL.
IT'S NEVER CHANGED.
EVERY TIME YOU COME HERE,
IT'S DELICIOUS.
THAT AIN'T NO ACCIDENT,
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU'RE BORN
INTO A LONG LINE
OF FRIED CHICKEN CHEFS,
LIKE LINNIE MOSEBERTH WAS.
CHICKEN BREAST SNACK UP.
HIS GRANDPARENTS STARTED
THE BIZ BACK IN 1940.
GOT THE HUSH PUPPIES
IN THERE.
NOW HE'S PASSIN' IT ON.
LEG SPECIAL,
BARBECUE SANDWICH.
YOU'RE THE F--
THIRD GENERATION.
AND YOU'RE THE FOURTH
GENERATION?
YES.
WELL, YOU'RE THE FOURTH
GENERATION BY MARRIAGE.
RIGHT. I'M HIS SON-IN-LAW.
HE'S NO DUMMY.
(laughter)
LET'S SEE.
"YOU'RE THE FRIED CHICKEN
PRINCESS?
LET ME THINK IF I WANT
TO MARRY--YEAH."
(laughter)
ONE REGULAR
FRIED CHICKEN DINNER.
IT'S JUICY ON THE INSIDE,
CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE.
TO DIE FOR.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE,
BROTHER?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME BATTER FOR THE CHICKEN.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF CHICKEN?
IN A DAY WE GO THROUGH
600, 700 POUNDS.
OF CHICKEN?
YEAH.
OKAY. BATTER--WE'RE GONNA
START OFF WITH A COUPLE WATERS,
FLOUR THAT'S ALREADY
BEEN SEASONED.
THIS--JUST ADD
SALT, PEPPER IN IT.
AN EGG WASH BATTER MIX.
OKAY.
BAKING SODA.
A LITTLE SALT
AND SOME PEPPER.
ENOUGH JUST TO MAKE
SOME COLOR TO IT.
AND THEN WE PUT WATER
ON TOP.
SO THIS WILL MAKE
HOW MUCH BATTER?
THIS IS ABOUT 6 GALLONS.
ARE WE READY TO ROCK?
YEAH.
(whirring)
OKAY. IT'S NOT GONNA EXPLODE
WHEN I OPEN IT, IS IT?
NO.
OHH! THIS IS THE SUBMARINE
THAT GOES TO FLAVOR TOWN.
WE'RE TALKIN' ABOUT
PANCAKE BATTER CONSISTENCY?
YES.
I LIKE IT.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO
FRY SOMETHIN'.
ALL RIGHTY.
OKAY, SO A BUNCH
OF THE BATTER.
AND YOU WATER IT DOWN?
JUST A BIT
TO THIN OUT
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
IT GETS A LITTLE TOO HARD
IF YOU HAVE TOO THICK A BATTER.
JUST GETS TOO HARD
OF A CRUNCH?
YEAH.
AND SOME PLAIN FLOUR.
OKAY.
SALT, PEPPER.
I LIKE THAT YOU'RE
LIBERAL WITH THE PEPPER.
AND WHOSE RECIPE WAS THIS?
MY GRANDPARENTS',
AND HAS BEEN KIND OF
PASSED ON--
BUT YOU HAVEN'T MESSED WITH IT?
NO. WE--WE TRY TO DO IT
THE SAME WAY.
GET A FEW PIECES OF CHICKEN
IN THERE FOR YOU.
SO IT GOES INTO THE WASH,
STICKS TO IT A LITTLE BIT.
MOVE IT AROUND.
SO NO WET HAND/DRY HAND
ON THIS TEAM?
NO.
YOU JUST WHEEL IT
RIGHT OVER?
YEP, GET IT RIGHT
INTO THE GREASE.
THIS THING LOOKS A LITTLE--
SHAKY? (laughs)
YEAH! "SHAKY" WOULD BE
THE WORD I WAS GONNA USE.
(sizzling)
AND THAT'S IT. 17 MINUTES--
HOW MANY--HOW MANY
PIECES WOULD--
17 MINUTES? (laughs)
YES.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
IS THAT RUNNIN' AT?
315.
COOKS SLOW SO IT COOKS
THE CHICKEN ALL THE WAY THOUGH,
THEN IT GETS IT NICE
AND CRISPY ON THE OUTSIDE.
CORRECT.
IT'S GONNA BE
SOME GOOD FRIED CHICKEN.
WE DONE?
YEAH. WE'RE READY.
PUT IT TOGETHER
WITH COLE SLAW, POTATO SALAD.
REGULAR DINNER
HAS A BREAST...
A THIGH...
EVIDENTLY, HE HAS NO FEELING
IN HIS FINGERS,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
A WING, AND A LONG LEG.
AND A LONG LEG?
YEAH.
THERE'S A SHORT-LEGGED
CHICKEN?
WHO WALKS IN CIRCLES.
A LOT OF PEOPLE CALL
THIS THIGH SHORT LEGS.
SO THAT'S A WHOLE
HALF A CHICKEN?
YES. HALF A CHICKEN,
AND SOME HUSH PUPPIES FOR YA.
LOOK AT THAT!
(crunches) MMM!
WHEN YOU COOK IT
LOW AND SLOW LIKE THAT,
YOU COOK THE FAT OUT,
YOU COOK THE MEAT.
MMM!
GETS IT NICE AND TENDER,
BUT THIS THING IS GONNA BE
CRUNCHENTATIOUS.
AND LOOK AT THAT.
THAT CRUNCHY BATTER.
OH, YES.
GOOD SEASONING TO IT.
IT'S NOT OILY.
NICE BIG PIECES OF CHICKEN.
MMM.
COOKED DOWN THE RIGHT WAY.
MY KIND OF FRIED CHICKEN.
YOU DELIVER
TO CALIFORNIA?
FOR YOU, YEAH. (laughs)
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
ONE REGULAR CHICKEN DINNER.
RIGHT.
ANY KETCHUP IN THE BAG?
SURE.
MY MOM MADE CHICKEN
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE GIRL,
BUT MY MOM DOESN'T HAVE ANYTHING
ON MOSEBERTH'S CHICKEN.
SORRY, MOM.
(crunches)
71 YEARS OF FRIED CHICKEN?
THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKIN' ABOUT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
OH, LET'S GET A CLOSE-UP
OF GUY RIGHT NOW.
LOOK WHAT HE'S DOING.
HE'S TAKING
A PICTURE OF HIMSELF.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
LOOK AT THAT GUY.
SO HANDSOME, SO SMART,
SO TALENTED.
I'M NOT EVEN T--
(laughs)
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE GUY
BEHIND YOU, GUY, NOT YOU.