HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LET'S SEE IT.
I'M LOADING UP THE CAMARO...
PACKAGE THOSE TO GO.
WITH SOME SCRATCH-MADE
CLASSICS.
FEEL LIKE I'M
AN EXPECTING FATHER.
IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
THE OLD-SCHOOL DINER...
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
BEING OLD-SCHOOL,
THAT'S YOUR POSTER
CHILD RIGHT THERE.
GETS A MASSIVE MAKEOVER...
WE'RE 21,800
OVER 4 FLOORS.
OH, MY GOD.
IN NEW YORK CITY...
LIKE, CRAZY SCIENTIST
ON ME NOW.
ONE SIDEWALK STAPLE
GETS A STEP UP...
I HAVEN'T HAD A PRETZEL
LIKE THIS IN 25 YEARS.
WHILE A SOUTHERN ONE
GOES LOWDOWN.
MMM. TAKE IT AWAY--
JUST AFTER ONE MORE BITE.
AND IN SANTA BARBARA...
ENCHILADA DINNER.
THE FAMILY-RUN
MEXICAN JOINT...
THAT'S WHEN MY MOUTH
JUST STARTS GOING NUTS.
CRANKIN' OUT CARNITAS
AND PASSING OUT POSOLE...
THAT'S THE BOMB.
ON MY KIND OF SCHEDULE.
HERE YOU CAN GET IT
EVERY DAY IF YOU WANT.
SEE? SEE THE HALO?
YEAH.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM
IN SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA.
NOW THERE'S A FEW THINGS
YOU CAN COUNT ON FOR SURE
WHEN YOU GET HERE--
THAT'S GREAT WEATHER,
AVOCADO TREES GALORE,
AND GREAT MEXICAN FOOD.
THE ONLY QUESTION IS,
HOW DO YOU TELL THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN ALL
THE MEXICAN RESTAURANTS?
FOR ME, IT'S ALL ABOUT QUALITY
AND AUTHENTICITY.
AND FROM WHAT I HEAR,
THE JOINT TO CHECK OUT
IS THIS PLACE--
LITO'S MEXICAN FOOD.
OKAY, GUYS, WE NEED...
(speaking indistinctly)
CARNITAS DINNER IS READY.
IT'S THE GREATEST MEXICAN FOOD,
I'M TELLING YOU,
IN, LIKE, THE WORLD.
REAL MEXICAN FOOD.
LIKE GOING TO MEXICO.
REAL MEXICAN.
THIS IS LIKE
A FAMILY OPERATION.
YOUR DAD STARTED THIS?
POP SAID WE WERE GONNA
OPEN UP A PLACE ON HALEY STREET,
AND I SAYS,
"OKAY, LET'S GO."
THAT WAS MORE THAN
30 YEARS AGO,
AND NOW SECOND GENERATION
ERNIE JIMENEZ...
ENCHILADA DINNER
DE POLLO.
RUNS THE JOINT.
SO YOU'VE SEEN
A LOT OF CHANGES,
BUT YOU GUYS HAVE
STAYED THE SAME.
LOT OF CHANGES.
YEAH, WE HAVE TO STAY THE SAME.
GOTTA BE CONSISTENT.
YOU GOTTA HAVE QUALITY,
AND YOU GOTTA BE AUTHENTIC.
EVEN DOWN TO THE POT
THEY'RE COOKING CARNITAS IN.
WHEN YOU SEE
A MEXICAN RESTAURANT,
AND THEY ARE ROCKIN'
THE POT
FOR CARNITAS, THIS IS WHAT
IT'S ALL ABOUT, BABY.
WHAT'S THE IMPORTANCE
OF HAVING THE COPPER POT?
TRADITION, THEY'RE
ALWAYS MADE IN COPPER.
MINE'S, LIKE,
STAINLESS STEEL.
WELL, THEY WON'T
TASTE RIGHT, STAINLESS STEEL.
OH, COME ON,
DON'T TELL ME THAT.
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE TO GO
TO MEXICO AND GET ONE.
I DON'T LIKE THAT ANSWER.
WHAT DO WE GOT IN HERE?
PORK FAT.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
GOT OUR PORK BUTTS
ALREADY BONED,
ALL READY TO GO.
THAT'S A PADDLE, BABY.
CAN PADDLE OUT TO
THE ISLANDS AND BACK
WITH THIS BABY
RIGHT HERE.
HOW LONG'S
IT GOTTA COOK?
ABOUT 3 HOURS.
350, ABOUT.
THAT'S WHEN MY MOUTH
JUST STARTS GOING NUTS.
NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
YOU CAN DEFINITELY SMELL IT.
NOW WHAT'S THE NEXT STEP?
NOW WE ADD OUR MILK.
MILK, REALLY?
THAT'S A NEW ONE FOR ME.
THEN WE WAIT ABOUT 10 OR 15
MINUTES, PUT OUR ORANGE JUICE.
NEXT--THE LEMON JUICE
AND THE SALT, OKAY.
LEMON JUICE AND SALT.
THEN WE PUT OUR CINNAMON BASE--
CINNAMON AND SUGAR.
SO WHAT IS IT? IS IT AN EXTRACT,
OR IS IT JUST--
NO, IT'S JUST MELTED
DOWN SUGAR...
OKAY.
AND THEN THE CINNAMON
WITH A LITTLE WATER.
THIS IS GONNA BE
FOR OUR COLOR.
AND THAT MELLOWS
IT ALL OUT.
NOW IT ALL SITS
IN THERE.
IT ALL SITS IN THERE
UNTIL THE WATER REDUCES.
LOOK AT THIS. OHH, NICE.
DIG IT. IT'S GOOD TO GO.
YEAH.
SMOKIN' HOT STILL.
LET'S SEE IT. I MEAN, JUST
FALL APART. LOOK AT THE COLOR.
GET TO A NICE PIECE
HERE FOR YOU.
GO AHEAD AND GIVE IT A WHACK
THERE WITH THE HATCHET THERE.
ALL RIGHT, THERE YOU GO.
OKAY. THERE YOU GO.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
THIS IS UP IN THE BEST
CARNITAS I'VE EVER HAD.
THIS HAS GREAT FLAVOR.
IT'S REALLY MOIST.
IT'S RICH, NOT TOO SALTY.
THIS YOUR RECIPE?
YES. HE'S BEEN DOING
IT FOR A LONG TIME, TOO.
YOU'RE NOT WORRIED--
HE KNOWS?
I'M NOT WORRIED.
A LITTLE STEAMED
TORTILLA.
OH, YEAH, YOU GOTTA
HAVE A TACO.
YEAH.
I LIKE THAT CRUNCH
YOU GET FROM THE CABBAGE.
BUT THE PORK, MAN,
THE MIXTURE OF THE MILK
AND THE CITRUS AND THE SALT
AND THEN THE SUGAR
AND THE CINNAMON--
PUT IT TOGETHER--THAT'S
SOME STAND-UP CARNITAS.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
CARNITAS TOSTADAS
READY TO GO.
CARNITAS...
CARNITAS TORTAS READY.
MY MAIN CRAVING.
REALLY TENDER.
REALLY FULL FLAVOR.
SLOW ROASTED.
YOU CAN TELL THEY TOOK
THEIR TIME WITH IT.
ERNIE GETS IN HERE EARLY IN
THE MORNING AND GETS IT GOING.
HOME COOKING. IT'S LIKE
GOING TO MOM'S HOUSE.
BUT EVEN MOM AIN'T ROCKIN'
THE TRADITIONAL PORK STEW
POSOLE LIKE THESE GUYS.
YOU CAN USUALLY ONLY GET IT ON
FRIDAY, SATURDAY, AND SUNDAY.
HERE, YOU CAN GET IT
EVERY DAY IF YOU WANT.
SEE? SEE THE HALO?
YEAH, SEE?
OH, THAT'S THE LIGHT.
HERE WE GO TO POSOLE LAND.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
HERE WE HAVE OUR CUBED UP
PORK MEAT HERE.
SO THIS IS THE TRI TIP
OF THE PIG.
RIGHT.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA COOK
THIS DOWN WITH SOME WATER.
WE GOT OUR ONIONS,
DRY OREGANO,
CUMIN, AND OUR GARLIC
BLENDED TOGETHER.
SIMMER FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR OR SO, 45 MINUTES.
UNTIL THE PORK
IS ALL COOKED.
NICE LITTLE SIMMER.
NOW WHAT?
WE ADD OUR HOMINY.
SEE THAT CORN? MMM.
GUAJILLO CHILI THAT
WE BLENDED ALREADY.
GUAJILLO CHILI IS
NOT REALLY SPICY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A BITE TO IT,
REALLY RICH IN FLAVOR.
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
OKAY, SO NOW
WE COOK THIS DOWN.
HOW MUCH LONGER
THIS IS GONNA GO?
ABOUT ANOTHER HALF AN HOUR,
READY TO GO.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
SERVE IT UP, BOSS.
LET'S DO THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
I FEEL LIKE I'M
AN EXPECTING FATHER.
AND THEN THE NICE LITTLE
PLATTER WITH SOME CABBAGE
AND SOME RADISH.
RADISHES.
I DO CILANTRO, ONIONS,
BUNCH OF THE CABBAGE.
OH, THERE'S NOTHING
THAT IS AS SATISFYING
IN THE SOUP WORLD
AS POSOLE.
BIG, TENDER, JUICY
PIECES OF PORK.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE CRUNCH,
'CAUSE THE CABBAGE
CAN SURVIVE.
AND THAT GUAJILLO PEPPER
IN THE BROTH--MMM.
THERE'S THE HOMINY
RIGHT THERE.
SOAKED UP ALL THAT
AWESOME FLAVOR. MMM.
THAT'S THE BOMB.
AWESOME.
PASS THE TEST?
PASS THE TEST? YOU WROTE
THE CURRICULUM, MY FRIEND.
LOOK AT THAT.
THANKS.
IN THE LIFETIME
THAT YOU'VE HAD POSOLE,
HOW DOES THAT RATE?
NUMBER ONE. EVERY WEEKEND,
GOTTA HAVE IT.
LITO'S IS THE STAPLE.
EVERYBODY KNOWS EVERYBODY.
IT'S A GREAT PLACE.
I LOVE IT, MAN. NICE PLACE.
NICE TO SEE THAT THE FAMILY
IS STILL RUNNING IT.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
TO GO.
YOU GOT IT.
MMM.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED NORTH
TO VAN-GROOVY B.C...
TURKEY FRIED RIBS,
CHICKEN SOUP.
WHERE A REBORN '50s DINER...
TAKE A LITTLE LOOKY-LOO.
IS A ONE-STOP SHOP
FOR THE CLASSICS.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
BEING OLD-SCHOOL,
THAT'S YOUR POSTER CHILD
RIGHT THERE.
SO WE'RE HERE
IN VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT OPENED
AS A BUTCHER SHOP IN 1957
THAT HAD A LITTLE LUNCH COUNTER
TO THE SIDE.
WELL, YEARS GO BY,
THE OWNER DECIDES TO RETIRE,
AND HE SHUTS THE DOORS--
UNTIL A LOCAL RESTAURANT OWNER
THAT WAS A BIG FAN OF THE PLACE
DECIDES TO REOPEN IT.
THIS TIME, HE DOESN'T JUST GO
FOR A LUNCH COUNTER,
HE GOES FOR A JOINT THAT'S
SERVING BREAKFAST, LUNCH,
AND DINNER, AND 95% OF THE FOOD
IS SCRATCH-MADE.
THIS IS THE NEW
SAVE-ON MEATS DINER.
RIBS ARE ALREADY IN.
OKAY, GUYS,
ORDERING FRIED CHICKEN.
EVERYTHING
USED TO BE DIFFERENT.
THEY TOTALLY
RENOVATED THE PLACE.
I MEAN, TOTALLY RENOVATED.
IT'S BACK,
AND IT'S WITH A FORCE.
'CAUSE WHEN OWNER MARK BRAND
BROUGHT THE 50-YEAR-OLD
JOINT BACK...
HOW WE DOIN'?
HE DID IT UP BIGGER
THAN EVER.
WE'RE 21,800
OVER 4 FLOORS.
OH, MY GOD.
FOUR FLOORS?
YEAH, STACKED FOR THE BAKERY,
A MEAT MARKET,
AND A FULL-SERVICE DINER
RUN BY CHEF JASON LEIZERT.
BANGERS AND MASH.
COMFORT DINER FOOD, REALLY.
CANADIAN FOOD, I CALL IT.
SCRATCH-MADE.
YEAH.
THAT'S RIGHT, SCRATCH COOKING
FROM START TO FINISH,
LIKE EVERY PIECE
OF THE TURKEY POT PIE.
IT'S SO GOOD. IT'S LIKE
MOM'S HOME COOKING.
IS THIS THE TURKEY
RIGHT HERE?
THAT IS THE TURKEY
RIGHT THERE.
ACTUALLY, WHY DON'T WE JUST
TRY THIS? JUST FOR SCIENCE,
NOT BECAUSE I WOULD EAT
ANY OF HIS MISE EN PLACE.
MMM. JUST THE BREAST,
OR THE WHOLE BIRD?
UH, WE DO THE WHOLE BIRD.
NICE.
OKAY, SO WE'RE STARTING OFF
WITH SMOKED TURKEY
POT PIE FILLING.
OH.
SWEATING DOWN ONIONS,
CARROTS, AND CELERY IN BUTTER
FOR TWO MINUTES.
YOU BETTER GET THIS STUFF
IN THERE FAST,
OR I'M GONNA EAT
ALL THE TURKEY.
OKAY, SO WE
SEASON THIS UP,
SALT, PEPPER,
THEN WE ADD OUR FLOUR.
MAKE A LITTLE ROUX.
THEN WE JUST
COOK THIS OUT
SO THE FLOUR
COOKS A LITTLE BIT.
AND YOU KEEP EATING
THE TURKEY.
OH, THIS ISN'T--I THOUGHT
IT WAS A SNACK--SNACK AREA.
WE'LL ADD OUR TURKEY.
ALL OF IT?
ALL OF IT, JUST SO YOU
DON'T EAT ANY MORE.
NOW WE'LL PUT OUR STOCK IN.
OKAY.
PEAS. LET ME THROW
A LITTLE BOUQUET IN.
BOUQUET GARNI RIGHT THERE.
GRAB SOME OF THE FLAVOR
FROM THAT, AND TAKE IT OUT
BEFORE WE START
BUILDING THE PIES.
YES, THAT IS TRUE.
SO WE'LL COOK THIS OUT FOR
PROBABLY ABOUT 25 TO 30 MINUTES,
UNTIL IT GETS
NICE AND THICK.
LET'S TALK ABOUT
MAKING PIE.
SO WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH OUR SAVORY DOUGH,
AND WE'RE GONNA START
IT OFF WITH BUTTER.
OKAY.
JUST A LITTLE MEDIUM SPEED,
SALT, ICING SUGAR,
ONE WHOLE EGG YOLK.
GIVE THAT A GOOD MIX.
FLOUR. SO WE HAVE
OUR DOUGH HERE,
AND WE JUST PUT
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
JUST TO MOISTEN IT
A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE THIS, ROLL THIS,
WRAP THIS, REST THIS...
YEP.
AND WE'LL COME OUT, ROLL IT OUT.
WHAT'S OUR NEXT ADVENTURE?
WE JUST FORM 'EM BY HAND.
WE FILL THIS WITH
OUR TURKEY POT PIE.
AND THEN WE TAKE OUR TOP, BRUSH
BOTH SIDES WITH SOME EGG WASH.
WE JUST CRIMP IT
RIGHT IN THERE.
ADD A LITTLE POKE THERE SO
THE STEAM DOESN'T BUILD UP.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
IN THE OVEN...
OKAY.
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES
AT 325.
TURKEY POT PIE.
BRING IT.
THERE WE GO.
YEAH, YOU OPEN THAT UP
RIGHT THERE.
MMM.
I LOVE ALL THE COMPONENTS--
THE HERBS, ROSEMARY.
ROSEMARY, THYME.
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
YOU GET THE SMOKINESS. MMM.
I MEAN, I THINK THE TURKEY HAD
SOME REALLY NICE FLAVOR TO IT,
BUT AS SOON AS YOU WARM IT UP,
IT EVEN BRINGS OUT
A LITTLE BIT MORE,
BUT, UH,
THE CRUST IS JUST
BOMB DOT COM FLAKY.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
SAVE-ON MEATS DINER
BEING OLD-SCHOOL, THAT'S
YOUR POSTER CHILD RIGHT THERE.
THANKS.
NICE JOB.
TURKEY POT PIE.
I'M LOVING THE GRAVY
AND THE CRUST.
GOTTA LOVE PIECRUST.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE POT PIE?
IT'S AWESOME. THERE'S SO MANY
VEGETABLES. PERFECT.
EVERYTHING
IS GOOD HERE.
CORNED BEEF.
FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
PROBABLY THE PORK CHOP.
I'M HAVING THE MEAT LOAF.
IT'S BETTER THAN MY MOM'S.
THERE'S A LOT OF THINGS
ON THE MENU THAT ARE GOOD,
BUT THE BURGER'S
THE GO-TO, FOR SURE.
AND IT'S BEEN THE GO-TO SINCE
BACK WHEN MARK WAS A KID.
WE USED TO COME HERE,
AND THEY HAD A BURGER
THAT WE USED
TO EAT RELIGIOUSLY.
THAT'S WHAT YOU
SURVIVED ON?
YEAH.
GREAT BURGER, HANDMADE PATTY.
HOMEMADE BUN. DELICIOUS.
WITH A MEAT MARKET NEXT DOOR,
IT BETTER BE A DANG GOOD BURGER.
IT IS.
HOW YOU GONNA
START IT OFF?
BARBECUE SAUCE.
THAT'S A GOOD WAY
TO START IT OFF. LET'S GO.
WE START OFF
WITH CANOLA OIL,
AND THEN WE ADD OUR ONIONS
AND GARLIC,
AND WE SWEAT THAT OFF.
SO THE GARLIC AND ONIONS
ARE WORKING. WHAT'S NEXT?
3 OUNCES OF WILD TURKEY
IN HERE.
I LIKE YOUR OUNCES.
THEN WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF VINEGAR, PEPPERCORNS,
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
CHIPOTLE PEPPERS...
OKAY.
SOME DARK MOLASSES,
A LITTLE TOMATO PASTE...
OKAY.
BAY LEAVES, CINNAMON--
CINNAMON?
YOU NEED ALL THOSE BACKGROUND
FLAVORS. BROWN SUGAR.
AND?
TOMATOES.
A LITTLE SALT, SOME FRESH
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
AND HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA SIMMER?
FOR ABOUT 25 MINUTES.
OKAY. ARE WE MAKING HAMBURGERS,
OR ARE WE MAKING MEAT LOAF?
WE ARE MAKING HAMBURGERS.
OKAY, ROCK 'N' ROLL.
WE GRIND OUR OWN MEAT,
AND THEN FROM HERE,
ROASTED GARLIC,
MUSTARD--DIJON...
WORCESTERSHIRE, TABASCO.
BREAD CRUMBS.
PERFECT FOR MEAT LOAF.
WHAT'S UP WITH THIS
MEAT LOAF THING?
ONIONS, FREE-RANGE EGGS,
ROSEMARY, THYME, PARSLEY.
YOU WANT TO SEASON IT UP
FOR ME?
YEAH, I'D LOVE TO.
LIKE THAT YOU'RE DOING
THE FRESH CRACKED PEPPER.
A LITTLE SALT.
THEN WE MIX THIS UP.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT
THIS ALL TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S IT.
THAT IS OUR BURGER.
WANT ME TO GET YOU A LOAF PAN
TO PUT THAT IN?
ALL THESE LITTLE JOKES.
COME ON, IT'S A HAMBURGER.
ABOUT 5 OUNCES WE DO.
FORM IT
RIGHT INSIDE THERE.
SO YOU GIVE THAT MEAT A CHANCE
TO REST A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE OIL ON THE FLATTOP.
THERE WE GO.
MMM, LOOK AT THAT.
SO MAYO, LETTUCE,
WITH OUR BURGER--
IT'S BEEN ON THE GRILL.
TAKE IT OFF.
BARBECUE SAUCE...
I LIKE THIS LITTLE DOCTOR'S TRAY
YOU'VE GOT GOING HERE.
BACON.
AND THEN A LITTLE MIX
OF WHITE CHEDDAR
AND ORANGE CHEDDAR.
IN THE SALLY.
SALAMANDER.
JUST TO MELT THAT
CHEESE DOWN.
OKAY.
BURGER COMES OUT OF THE SALLY,
RIGHT ONTO HERE.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
(whistles) NICE.
I DON'T TYPICALLY
CUT MY BURGERS IN HALF,
BUT FOR ALL MY FRIENDS
THAT ARE WATCHING RIGHT NOW,
LET'S TAKE A LITTLE
LOOKY-LOO. HERE IT COMES.
THIS IS NOT SHORT OF FLAVOR.
I PICK UP A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ROSEMARY.
THE BARBECUE SAUCE
HAS DEFINITELY GOT SOME KICK.
AND THE BACON...
DOESN'T FALL SHORT
BY ANY MEANS.
AND THE FACT THAT
YOU DID EVERYTHING
EXCEPT FOR RAISE THAT STEER
AND MAKE THAT BACON--
PRETTY GOOD DEAL.
NICE JOB.
(woman) SAVE-ON BURGER.
I SAW THE BURGER AGAIN,
AND I HAD TO ORDER IT.
DON'T CHEAT YOURSELF, IF YOU'VE
GOT A GOOD THING, STICK WITH IT.
CHEDDAR CHEESE, BACON--
EVERYTHING YOU NEED ON IT.
ALL RIGHT, FRIED CHICKEN.
NUMBER ONE CHOICE FOR BREAKFAST,
FOR DINNER, FOR LUNCH.
THIS IS BEING ABLE
TO BRING KIDS DOWN HERE
AND SHOWING 'EM
WHAT A DINER WAS LIKE.
THAT'S IT,
AND YOU SEE A LOT OF FAMILIES
IN HERE, A LOT OF PEOPLE SAYING,
"MY GRANDMOTHER USED
TO TAKE ME HERE,
SO I'M BRINGING
MY KIDS HERE."
CONGRATULATIONS, BROTHER.
RIGHT ON, MAN.
VERY HAPPY FOR YOU.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO MANHATTAN'S EAST VILLAGE...
LIVIN' ON THE EDGE.
WHERE A SOUTHERN
COMFORT JOINT...
THERE'S NO WAY THAT'S
ENOUGH CHEESE FOR ME.
I'D HAVE TO MAKE THIS
IN A BATHTUB.
IS TWISTING UP
A NEW YORK STAPLE.
WE'RE HERE IN THE EAST VILLAGE
IN NEW YORK CITY
ON 13th STREET
TO CHECK OUT A PLACE
THAT'S OWNED BY SOME FOLKS
WITH SOME SERIOUS FINE DINING
RESTAURANT CREDENTIALS.
WELL, THEN THEY DECIDED
TO CHANGE THINGS UP
AND OPEN UP
A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT.
AND BECAUSE OF THE FACT
THAT MY GRANDMA, MY MOM,
MY AUNT, AND MY SISTER
ARE ALL REDHEADS,
WELL, I JUST HAD TO CHECK
IT OUT. THIS IS THE REDHEAD.
(man) HERE WE HAVE THE PORK
CHOP, BUTTERMILK FRIED CHICKEN.
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS JUST INCREDIBLE.
NEWPORT STEAK
IN THE WINDOW.
I THINK CHEF MEG HAS, LIKE,
SPECIAL POWERS.
THAT'D BE CHEF MEG GRACE...
CHAR IN THE WINDOW.
WHO DECIDED IN 2006
TO USE HER SPECIAL POWERS
TO OPEN HER OWN JOINT...
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
WITH HUSBAND ROB LARCOM
AND BUSINESS PARTNER
GREGG NELSON.
I WAS EXPECTING ONE OF YOU
TO BE A REDHEAD.
YEAH. WE KIND OF
EXPLAIN IT A LOT.
SO WHY DID YOU CALL IT
THE REDHEAD?
BOTH HISTORY BUFFS--
DURING THE PROHIBITION ERA,
THERE WAS A FAMOUS RESTAURANT
CALLED THE REDHEAD BAR.
SO IT WAS A SPEAKEASY.
NICE.
ORDER FIRE
PRETZEL AND CHEESE.
NEW YORK HISTORY
ALSO PLAYS A BIG PART
IN MEG'S MENU.
PRETZEL AND BEER CHEESE
IN THE WINDOW.
STARTING WITH HER TAKE
ON A BIG APPLE STAPLE.
(woman) THE PRETZELS ARE
WONDERFUL.
THEY'RE ALWAYS A TREAT.
NOT LIKE STREET PRETZELS,
WHICH ARE HARD, THEY JUST
KIND OF MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
LOVE THE BEER CHEESE.
IT EMBARRASSES
EVERY PRETZEL
THAT YOU BUY ON THE STREET.
IT DOES.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOFT PRETZELS.
LIKE NEW YORK-STYLE
SOFT PRETZELS?
LIKE GERMAN-STYLE
SOFT PRETZELS.
SO WE GET STARTED,
WE HAVE SOME SUGAR.
SUGAR FOR THE YEAST.
SUGAR, THEN WE ADD
THE WATER.
WE'RE GONNA SPRINKLE
THE YEAST ON TOP,
AND WE'RE GONNA
LET THAT BLOOM.
NOW WE'VE GOT
BLOOMED YEAST.
I'M GONNA ADD
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
THEN I'M GONNA ADD
WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR.
FOR TEXTURE?
FLAVOR.
FLAVOR, COLOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF TEXTURE, BECAUSE
IT'S FAIRLY COARSELY GROUND.
AND THIS IS WHITE RYE FLOUR,
AND THAT'S FOR FLAVOR.
KOSHER SALT, MALT POWDER,
AND MELTED BUTTER.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE MIX THIS.
WE'RE GONNA COVER IT
AND LET IT RISE.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE HAVE
OUR RISEN DOUGH.
HOW MANY PRETZELS
WILL THIS MAKE?
ABOUT 20. SO WE'RE
GONNA CUT THIS IN HALF,
AND THEN WE'RE
GONNA CUT EACH HALF.
WE ROLL 'EM OUT
INTO ROPES.
OKAY.
AND THEN YOU LOOP IT AROUND
FORMING A PRETZEL.
HOW MANY BATCHES OF THIS
DO YOU MAKE A WEEK?
WE MAKE IT FRESH
EVERY DAY.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE ALL THIS TIME
TO HAND-ROLL PRETZELS.
YOU'RE A GLUTTON
FOR PUNISHMENT
OR YOU JUST HAVE
AN ISSUE WITH SLEEPING.
IT'S THE RIGHT WAY
TO DO IT.
I-I'M DOWN
WITH THE RIGHT WAY.
SO WE MAKE THE LYE SOLUTION.
THAT'S THE FOOD-GRADE LYE.
PUT THE LYE IN THE BOTTOM
OF THE BOWL, SALT,
WARM WATER, AND WE STEP
BACK A LITTLE BIT,
'CAUSE IT'S GONNA
BUBBLE UP.
LIKE, CRAZY SCIENTIST
ON ME NOW.
THESE HAVE BEEN CHILLED,
AND THEY HAVE THEIR SKIN,
SO THEY'RE REALLY EASY
TO DEAL WITH...
OKAY.
ESPECIALLY SINCE WE'RE GONNA
PUT 'EM IN HOT WATER.
DUNK 'EM ALL IN.
LYE WATER MAKES
THAT BEAUTIFUL BROWN COLOR
AND A NICE GLOSS.
AH.
WHAT IS THE CHEMICAL REACTION
THAT'S HAPPENING HERE
THAT'S GIVING IT
THIS BROWN COLOR?
IT'S THE SAME REACTION THAT
HAPPENS ON THE OUTSIDE OF MEAT
WHEN YOU SEAR IT.
REALLY? IF I WANTED TO GET
A LITTLE MORE TAN...
BAD IDEA. SALT.
ALL RIGHT, SO BAKE 'EM OFF
AT WHAT TEMP?
400.
SEVEN TO EIGHT MINUTES.
WHILE WE'RE DOING THAT,
WE MAKE THE CHEESE SAUCE.
YES.
WORD.
A LITTLE OIL,
SHALLOTS, GARLIC.
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
SAUTé THESE A LITTLE BIT...
OKAY.
SO THEY'RE NOT RAW.
CREAM CHEESE, SHREDDED
AGED WHITE CHEDDAR,
OUR SHALLOTS AND ONIONS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD THE BEER.
IT'S NOT GONNA TAKE MUCH.
AND THERE WE GO.
WE'RE DUMPING THIS OUT
INTO A TAMIS
AND PUSHING IT THROUGH SO WE GET
ALL THE LITTLE BITS OUT.
ALL RIGHT,
WE PUSH THIS THROUGH.
WOW, THAT IS JUST SMOOTH
AND CREAMY.
NOW WORCESTERSHIRE...
THIS JUST CONTINUES
TO GET BETTER.
DRIED MUSTARD,
CAJUN SEASONING, WHICH IS,
LIKE, DRIED ONION, THYME,
HERBS, TABASCO,
SALT.
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
SO WE CHILL IT, LET IT
TIGHTEN UP A LITTLE BIT.
YEP.
SO THIS IS THE CHILLED
BEER CHEESE.
IT GOES INTO, LIKE,
A 3-OUNCE RAMEKIN.
THERE'S NO WAY THAT'S
ENOUGH CHEESE FOR ME.
SO YOU HAVE
OUR HOT PRETZELS,
AND THAT'S WHAT GOES
TO THE TABLE.
THAT'S WHAT GOES
TO THE MOUTH.
I GET THAT WHEAT.
YEAH.
NICE, SOFT, A LITTLE BIT
OF CRUST ON 'EM,
THAT SMOOTH GLAZE,
SOME SALT.
I HAVEN'T HAD A PRETZEL
LIKE THIS IN 25 YEARS.
AND NOW--DO YOU
SERVE THE PRETZEL
JUST SO YOU CAN USE IT
TO SHOVEL IT IN?
YEAH.
THE CREAMINESS,
THE SALTINESS, THE TANG,
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SPICE.
I REALLY DIDN'T THINK
IT WAS GONNA BE ENOUGH,
BUT THAT IS
PACKING-THE-PUNCH CHEESE.
THAT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
PRETZEL IN THE WINDOW.
THE PRETZELS MEG MAKES
ARE THE ONES I THINK EVERYBODY
LONGS FOR, 'CAUSE THE ONES
YOU GET ON THE STREET
DON'T TASTE LIKE THAT.
NO.
UP NEXT...
NICE CALL.
THE MENU AT THE REDHEAD
IS GOING SOUTH...
I'M A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL.
RIGHT ON.
FOR A LOW COUNTRY CLASSIC.
I'VE HAD THIS IN A LOT OF WAYS
IN A LOT OF PLACES
BY A LOT OF FOLKS,
BUT THIS IS EXCEPTIONAL.
AT THE REDHEAD
IN MANHATTAN'S EAST VILLAGE,
CHEF MEG GRACE
IS FULL OF SURPRISES.
PRETZEL IN THE WINDOW.
(woman) IT'S ONE OF THOSE
PLACES THAT YOU JUST KNOW
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
NEW AND DIFFERENT,
BUT THEN THEY KEEP THE CLASSICS
ON THE MENU, TOO.
ALWAYS A SOUTHERN FLAIR
FOR MEG, TOO.
NEWPORT IN THE WINDOW.
WE'RE TALKING
BUTTERMILK FRIED CHICKEN,
PORK CHOPS...
PORK CHOP
IN THE WINDOW.
AND THIS CLASSIC,
WHICH I'M NOT SURE
YOU CAN EVEN LEGALLY EAT
THIS FAR NORTH.
IT'S A LOW COUNTRY
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
CALLED LOW COUNTRY
BECAUSE...
SOUTH CAROLINA.
LOW IN THE COUNTRY.
GEORGIA.
I'M A GRIT-EATIN' FOOL.
RIGHT ON. MILK.
CREAM?
MORE MILK.
IT'S ALL MILK.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
OH, THESE ARE
GONNA BE CREAMY.
SO WE'RE GONNA
BRING THAT TO A BOIL
AND THEN STIR
THE GRITS IN.
THESE ARE SOME
NICE STONE-GROUND?
YES. SO THEY'LL COME
TO A SIMMER,
AND THEY'LL SORT OF
START TO THICKEN.
OKAY, SO THE GRITS
ARE COOKED DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA FINISH THEM...
MELD THEM WITH BUTTER?
MELD THEM WITH BUTTER
AND MASCARPONE CHEESE...
WOW.
MORE SALT, PEPPER.
EACH TIME YOU MAKE THIS, YOU
HAVE THE BIG POT OF GRITS DONE.
YOU MAKE THE SHRIMP?
YEAH, WE DO THAT
TO ORDER.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
WE'RE GONNA SEASON OUR SHRIMP--
SALT,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER.
I LIKE THE LITTLE
SKEWER IDEA.
IT MAKES IT A LITTLE FASTER
FOR THE COOK.
I'M RIPPING THAT OFF.
SO WE JUST GET
A LITTLE COLOR ON THERE.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT BACK
AND ADD OUR ANDOUILLE.
THAT RENDERS OUT A LITTLE BIT
MORE FAT FOR US.
ONION, CELERY,
BELL PEPPER...
CAJUN COOKING.
A LITTLE MORE PEPPER,
OUR GARLIC.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PULL
OFF THE FLAMES,
SO WE DON'T CATCH
OURSELVES ON FIRE.
HIT IT WITH SOME BRANDY,
SHRIMP STOCK.
NICE CALL.
NOW WE ADD
OUR SHRIMP BACK IN.
BUTTER, PARSLEY.
OKAY, SO THYME,
PARSLEY, AND...
CHIVES.
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
A LITTLE BIT OF LEMON,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO.
SO YOU GET
YOUR GRITS FIRST.
♪♪
AND THERE IT IS.
THIS HAS A REAL NICE BALANCE
WITH THE--THE HERBS...
THE FOUNDATION OF THAT JUICE,
A LITTLE PINCH OF THE GARLIC,
BUT A REALLY NICE
STRONG SHRIMP FLAVOR.
THE GRITS THEMSELVES
HAVE FANTASTIC TEXTURE.
THIS WILL FILL YOU UP,
AND I'VE HAD FOUR OR FIVE--
15 BITES.
I'VE HAD THIS IN A LOT OF WAYS
IN A LOT OF PLACES
BY A LOT OF FOLKS,
BUT THIS IS EXCEPTIONAL.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
TAKE IT AWAY--
JUST AFTER ONE MORE BITE.
(man) SHRIMP AND GRITS.
(Guy) HOW ARE
THE SHRIMP AND GRITS?
IT'S THE KIND OF FOOD YOU
ALWAYS CRAVE. IT'S SO GOOD.
(woman) YOU CAN GET ALL THOSE
COMFORT FOODS THAT YOU LOVE,
BUT IT ALSO FEELS
A LITTLE SPECIAL,
BECAUSE THE FOOD
IS PREPARED SO WELL
AND LOOKS SO BEAUTIFUL
ON THE PLATE.
FRESH INGREDIENTS,
FRESH FOOD.
YOU CAN COME IN HERE
IN YOUR JEANS
AND WATCH THE RED SOX LOSE
AND HAVE A BEER AND PRETZEL
OR...
WAIT A SECOND.
OOPS, THAT JUST
CAME OUT?
(voices overlapping)
PLEASE MAKE SURE
THAT MAKES THE EDIT, OKAY?
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY, WE GOT
PLENTY MORE JOINTS TO FIND
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE INS AND DIVES."
ONE MORE THING.
(laughter)
PACKAGE THOSE TO GO.