HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
BRING IT.
SOUTHERN COMFORT...
THAT'S ABOUT
AS SOUTHERN
AS IT GETS
RIGHT THERE.
ACROSS THE CONTINENT.
IS THAT LEGAL?
APPARENTLY.
IN VANCOUVER, B.C.,
THE MODERN-DAY DINER...
PORK BELLY
IN THE WINDOW.
DEEP-FRYING BACON...
WHAT?
YEAH.
DO YOU KNOW
NO BOUNDARIES?
AND FLIPPIN'
MY KIND OF CAKES.
IT'S THE PULLED PORK PANCAKES
WITH JACK DANIEL'S MAPLE SYRUP.
IN
SUMMERVILLE, SOUTH CAROLINA...
FRANKIE ELVIS.
THE HOT DOG JOINT
WHERE ONE ALL-AMERICAN...
LOOK AT THAT GUY.
PERRY IS
A SUMMERVILLE ICON.
IS SERVIN' UP ANOTHER.
DON'T GO SKIMPY ON THE CHILI.
(clearing throat)
THAT'S A RIGHTEOUS DOG.
AND IN N.Y.C.--
YEAH, NEW YORK CITY, BABY--
FRIED CHICKEN...
(man)
WHAT DO YOU PREFER?
ALL OF IT.
A PEACH COBBLER
JUST LIKE MAMA'S.
A LITTLE PIECE
OF HEAVEN.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN EAST VANCOUVER, CANADA,
OR "EAST VAN"
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE I HEAR THE OWNER SAYS
HIS FOOD WILL TAKE YOU
ON A WILD RIDE,
KIND OF LIKE THE WILD RIDES
HE USED TO TAKE
IN HIS LITTLE RED WAGON.
WELL, I GUESS THAT'S WHY HE
CALLS THE JOINT THE RED WAGON.
PULLED PORK PANCAKES IN
THE WINDOW. PICK-UP, PLEASE.
(bell dings)
(man) CREATIVE COMBINATIONS
OF CLASSIC FOOD.
THE RED WAGON
IS COMPLETELY UNIQUE.
RIGHT DOWN TO THE NAME.
CAN YOU SAY IT
FIVE TIMES FAST?
(speaking indistinctly)
RED WAGON RIDER,
WED WAGON RIDER...
RED WAGON RIDER.
WED WAGON RIDER.
IT'S A TONGUE-TWISTER THAT CAME
FROM BRAD MILLER'S CHILDHOOD.
SO YOU GUYS USED TO RIDE
THE RED WAGON.
YEAH.
WE USED TO GO DOWN
A ROCK HILL BASICALLY.
IN THE WAGON?
IN THE WAGON.
THESE CLOWNS. THIS IS
THE RED WAGON TRIO.
THAT'S US.
SO TAKING A CHANCE
AS A FIRST-TIME
RESTAURANT OWNER
WAS REALLY NO BIG DEAL.
BASICALLY, I SAW IT
FOR SALE, AND I BOUGHT IT.
IT HELPS THAT BRAD'S
A FRENCH-TRAINED CHEF
WHO'S CRANKIN' OUT CLASSICS
LIKE SHORT RIBS WITH BRIE,
THE CROQUE MADAME,
OR A CRISPY PORK BELLY
THAT'S TAKIN' BACON
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
PORK BELLY
IN THE WINDOW.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE PUTTING TOGETHER THE RUB
FOR OUR PORK BELLY.
OKAY.
BLACK PEPPER.
I GOT--
CINNAMON-AMON-AMON.
CIN--YEAH,
EXACTLY, SIR.
THAT WAS A HARD ONE FOR ME
AS A KID.
YEAH, IT'S--
CLOVE, CRUSHED-UP
BAY LEAVES IN THERE,
KOSHER SALT,
AND WE GOT SOME PINK SALT
THAT'S GONNA GO
IN THERE AS WELL.
WHITE PINK SALT?
WELL, YEAH. I DON'T EVER
SEE IT TINTED UP HERE.
OH, REALLY?
YEAH. A LITTLE BIT OF GROUND
ALLSPICE TO FINISH.
WE JUST MIX IT UP.
THERE WE GO.
WE'RE GONNA GET
A PORK BELLY OUT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA SKIN THIS GUY.
GLOVES ON.
DOCTOR.
DOCTOR, INDEED.
SO THERE YOU GO.
JUST A NICE, LITTLE,
UH, GENEROUS RUB.
HERE WE GO. WE GET A LITTLE BIT
OF DRY WHITE WINE
JUST TO, UH...
COCKTAIL YOU HAD
LEFT OVER, OKAY.
GOT SOME FRESH THYME.
THYME.
WE GOT SOME BRANDY
GOING IN THERE, TOO.
MMM.
LET THAT JUST GO
ABOUT A WEEK.
36 HOURS.
36, OKAY. NEXT STEP?
IT SITS INTO THE PAN
LIKE THAT.
WE'RE GONNA CONFIT IT.
WE'RE GONNA COOK IT
IN ITS OWN FAT,
IF YOU WILL.
HUH.
WE HAVE EL HOT TUBBO
OF PIG FATTO IN THERE.
INDEEDY, WE DO.
"INDEEDY, WE DO."
INDEEDY.
JUST ENOUGH
TO BE DANGEROUS.
THIS SHOULD BE ILLEGAL.
COVER IT.
5 HOURS AT 200, 225.
ALL RIGHT.
MMM. MM-HMM.
THERE SHE BE.
COME ON DOWN
TO THE FLAVORTOWN FAIR,
WHERE IT'S THE BOBBING
FOR THE CONFITED PORK BELLY.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
TAKE IT OUT AND COOL IT DOWN.
I LIKE THAT IT DIDN'T RENDER
ALL THE FAT THAT'S ON IT.
YEAH, WE TRY NOT
TO GO TOO FAR.
SO SHE'S GOING
IN THE FRIDGE.
WHY?
TO COOL DOWN,
FIRM UP.
NO, NO, NO,
WHY? WHY?
LOOK AT THAT. IT JUST FELL OFF,
FELL RIGHT OFF IN MY HAND.
YOU GUYS SAW IT.
(laughing)
I JUST WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENS IF I STEAL THAT.
I MEAN, AM I LOOKING
AT HARD TIME?
THAT DEPENDS
IF THEY CATCH YOU OR NOT.
YEAH, THAT'S
A GOOD POINT.
I WOULD SAY, YEAH.
I'M PRETTY--I'M PRETTY
INCOGNITO WITH THE HAIR...
I IMAGINE--
AND THE--
AND THE RED CAMARO.
EXACTLY.
SO HOW DO WE
SERVE THIS?
WE'RE GONNA
DEEP-FRY IT.
(bell dings)
WHAT?
YEAH.
DO YOU KNOW
NO BOUNDARIES?
DOWN SHE GOES.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS WITH?
WE'RE GONNA USE SOME--
A COUPLE
HEART PADDLES?
BRING IT TOGETHER,
BROTHER.
WE GOT SOME HOME FRIES
HERE, A LITTLE TOMATO.
WE GOT A NICE
LITTLE CONFITED PORK BELLY,
SOME NICE SUNNY EGGS.
WE'VE GOT SOME SALSA VERDE HERE,
BASICALLY--A TOMATILLO SALSA
WE USE ON IT
AND SOME HOLLANDAISE
JUST TO FINISH IT UP.
♪ HEY, HEY ♪
MMM. CONFITED PORK BELLY
WITH THAT NICE RUB,
A LITTLE BIT OF HERB TO IT,
THE WHITE WINE,
THE BUTTER OF THE FAT--
AND I DROOL
AS I TELL YOU ABOUT IT.
MMM, THAT IS DYNAMITE.
EXECUTED PERFECTLY,
PUT TOGETHER--
JUST A GREAT MIX
OF FLAVORS.
AND IF YOU'RE GONNA DO IT,
IF YOU'RE GONNA GO BIG,
THEN DO IT THE RIGHT WAY.
AND THAT RIGHT THERE,
MY FRIEND, IS TREATING IT
WITH UTMOST RESPECT.
MMM. KNOCKED IT OUT.
THANK YOU.
GET IT AWAY FROM ME.
SERIOUSLY.
THAT OR YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO REMODEL THIS PLACE
TO GET ME
OUT THE FRONT DOOR.
PORK BELLY
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S REALLY CRISP,
AND IT'S REALLY SALTY.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE
DISH HERE.
IT'S JUST HONEST FOOD. IT
EXCEEDS PEOPLE'S EXPECTATIONS.
RUEBEN AND PULLED PORK PANCAKE
FOR 11, PLEASE. PICK UP.
(bell dings)
ITEM ON THE MENU
THAT YOU'RE MOST PROUD OF?
THE PULLED PORK PANCAKES.
(man) I PRETTY MUCH GET THIS
EVERY TIME I COME HERE.
THE PULLED PORK
AT THE RED WAGON IS TOP-NOTCH.
PULLED PORK PANCAKES.
IT ALL STARTS WITH A PORK BUTT
COVERED IN BRAD'S
SIGNATURE RUB.
A TRIMMED-DOWN PORK BUTT--
GIVE IT A GENEROUS RUB.
YEAH.
YOU GONNA LET THIS REST AT ALL,
OR ARE WE JUST READY TO GO?
36 HOURS, OPTIMALLY,
IN THE FRIDGE.
AND THEN GO INTO THE SMOKER,
HITTING IT WITH THE APPLE.
HOW MUCH TIME
IN THE SMOKER?
EXACTLY.
FOUR TO FIVE HOURS.
WE GET IT INTO A PAN. WE DOUSE
IT WITH A LITTLE SOMETHIN'.
YOU DOUSE IT WITH
A LITTLE SOMETHIN'.
WE GOT A LITTLE BEER
THAT WE USE ON THAT.
IN SHE GOES.
NOW YOU'RE
GONNA WRAP IT?
YEAH. WE'RE GONNA
COVER IT UP.
POP IT IN THE OVEN,
250 FOR HOW LONG?
250--
ANOTHER 3, 4 HOURS?
YEAH, TILL WE GOT
HER TENDER. EXACTLY.
AND THIS IS GOING
FOR WHAT AGAIN?
IT'S THE PULLED PORK PANCAKES
WITH JACK DANIEL'S MAPLE SYRUP.
WHY DOES THAT SOUND
LIKE HE MADE THAT
AT ABOUT 4:30
IN THE MORNING?
THERE'S OUR PORK,
FRESH OUT OF THE OVEN.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WHAT?
I'M GONNA RESERVE THE JUICE
SO I CAN HEAT IT UP
WITH THE PORK.
LET THAT COOL
A LITTLE BIT?
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA
SHRED IT.
SHRED IT
AND MAKE THE SYRUP.
YEP. WE GOT A LITER
OF LIGHT MAPLE SYRUP.
SECRET INGREDIENT
OVER HERE FOR YOU.
OKAY. THIS IS THE FAMOUS ELIXIR
OF LYNCHBURG, TENNESSEE.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE A BIT
OF JACK DANIEL'S IN THERE.
THAT'S ABOUT A CUP...
YEAH.
TO A QUART.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
EXACTLY. BASICALLY BRING IT
UP TO A BOIL AND SHUT HER OFF.
AND THEN WE'LL BUILD
SOME PANCAKES.
LET'S ROLL.
A LITTLE BIT OF CANOLA OIL
ON THE GRIDDLE.
THAT IS SOME LUMPY, LUMPY,
LUMPY PANCAKE BATTER.
LUMPY INDEED, YEAH.
NOW WHAT?
CAKES ARE WORKIN'. THAT'S
OUR PULLED PORK RIGHT THERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH--
THAT'S THE COOKIN'
LIQUID FROM IT.
THAT'S A LITTLE BIT
OF THE LITTLE--
GELATINOUS
FANTASTIC-NESS?
THAT'S OUR
SMOKED PORK DEMI.
AND WHAT IS THIS?
BARBECUE SAUCE.
SO ALL THIS COOKS UP
TOGETHER?
YEP.
WE WANT TO HAVE SOME CHUNKS,
BUT WE ALSO WANT TO BE ABLE
TO SPREAD IT
ACROSS--YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA FLIP 'EM
OVER NOW. LET'S GO.
OKAY.
AND THEN WATCH 'EM...
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT THING PUFF.
IT'S LIKE PUFF-O-MATIC.
SO OUR CAKES
ARE ALMOST READY HERE.
BUILD 'EM RIGHT HERE
ON THE FLATTOP.
JUST LAY DOWN SOME PORK.
AND WE'RE GONNA LAYER
THESE GUYS UP.
THAT'S GOOD.
THERE WE GO. COMING ACROSS
THE PLATE, YEAH?
THERE WE HAVE IT--
PULLED PORK PANCAKES.
THEN JUST OVER THE TOP
WITH SOME OF THE...
WOW, YOU CAN SMELL
THE JACK.
J.D. SYRUP.
YOU MOUNT IT
WITH A LITTLE BUTTER.
THAT'S--THAT'S
HOW WE DO IT.
DIG IN.
WOW.
IT'S LIKE A SPLIT-PERSONALITY
BREAKFAST.
REALLY NICE
BUTTERMILK PANCAKE--
AND I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN'
THICK AND RICH.
AND THE MAPLE SYRUP
WITH A LITTLE TINGE
OF THAT JACK DANIEL'S
COMING THROUGH. MMM.
YEAH, A LITTLE
SWEETNESS.
BUT NOW YOU GET BARBECUE.
IT'S GREAT PULLED PORK.
AND THEN YOU'RE RIGHT BACK
INTO SWEETNESS.
(speaking indistinctly)
NICE JOB, MAN.
NICE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WOW. I NEED A CUP OF COFFEE
AFTER THAT.
(laughing)
(Guy) 'CAUSE PANCAKES
AND PULLED PORK--ODD?
THEY'RE--IT'S ODD,
BUT IT WORKS.
IT'S SALTY AND SWEET, BUT IT'S
REALLY AWESOME TOGETHER.
THE FOOD IS QUALITY. YOU CARE
ABOUT EVERY PLATE THAT GOES OUT.
PEOPLE DEFINITELY LOVE IT.
CONGRATULATIONS, MAN. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU, SIR.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO SUMMERVILLE, SOUTH CAROLINA,
FOR A DRESSED-UP DOG...
FRANKIE ELVIS.
YOU GOTTA TRY
THAT ONE.
WITH A HOMETOWN HERO.
DON'T GO SKIMPY
ON THE CHILI.
DO I HAVE ANY? HUH?
NO. NOT AT ALL.
I GOT A GREAT STORY FOR YOU.
I'M HERE
IN SUMMERVILLE, SOUTH CAROLINA,
ABOUT 20 MILES WEST
OF CHARLESTON.
NOW THIS IS WHERE
A LOCAL FOOTBALL STAR
WHO GOES ON TO PLAY FOR ALABAMA
HAS A CAREER-ENDING INJURY.
SO WHAT'S HE DECIDE TO DO?
YEP, COME BACK TO HIS HOMETOWN
AND OPEN UP EXACTLY WHAT THEY
NEEDED--A HOT DOG JOINT.
THIS IS PERFECTLY FRANK'S.
FRANKIE ELVIS.
FRENCH TOAST FRANKIE.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU COULD DO
SO MANY THINGS WITH A HOT DOG.
SO WHAT MAKES THIS PLACE
SO GOOD?
IT'S NOT ONLY THE FOOD.
PERRY WAS A STAR QUARTERBACK
ON THE HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL TEAM
IN THE LATE '70s.
ORDER UP!
THAT'D BE PERRY CUDA,
WHO DREW UP
A WHOLE NEW PLAYBOOK FOR DOGS
BACK IN '07.
HE HAS SO MANY DIFFERENT THINGS
THAT HE PUTS ON A HOT DOG...
(Perry) PULLED PORK.
BANANAS AND PEANUT BUTTER
AND BACON...
MACARONI AND CHEESE.
ANYTHING YOU CAN IMAGINE
ON A HOT DOG.
ALL RIGHT,
FRANK CUDA DOG UP.
I LIKE THE ONE
HE NAMED AFTER HIS DAD
WITH BLUE CHEESE
COLE SLAW.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
THE FRANK CUDA.
SO THIS IS NAMED
AFTER YOUR DAD?
IT IS.
OKAY, LET'S GET
INTO THE CHILI.
OKAY.
WHOSE RECIPE?
MY RECIPE.
FIRST THING IN--
80/20?
YEP, GROUND BEEF,
DICED ONION,
GRANULATED GARLIC, CUMIN...
OREGANO.
OREGANO, YES, SIR,
BROWN SUGAR...
NICE CALL.
PAPRIKA...
CHILI POWDER.
CHILI POWDER, A LITTLE YELLOW
MUSTARD, WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
TABASCO...
(whistles)
CRUSHED TOMATOES,
AND CINNAMON,
RED CHILI FLAKE,
AND SOME OLIVE OIL.
HOW LONG YOU GONNA LET
THIS COOK DOWN--
TILL THAT MEAT JUST BREAKS
UP INTO LITTLE PIECES...
EXACTLY.
REALLY NICE AND THIN?
ABOUT 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR.
WHAT KIND OF DOG ARE WE
GONNA PUT IT ON?
A NATHAN'S DOG.
MMM.
ALL BEEF, SKINLESS,
YEAH, READY TO GO.
WHAT ARE WE INTO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE BLUE CHEESE COLE SLAW.
SHREDDED CABBAGE,
SHREDDED CARROTS.
NO CULINARY CLASSES
FOR YOU...
HOME, SCHOOL--
JUST EXPERIMENTING
ON YOUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY.
EXACTLY. A LITTLE COLE SLAW
DRESSING, MAYONNAISE, SUGAR,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
CELERY SEED,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
AND CRUMBLED BLUE CHEESE.
AND WE JUST MIX IT UP
BY HAND.
WHAT OTHER BODY PART
WOULD YOU MIX IT WITH?
WELL... (laughing)
GIMME A HIGH FIVE.
TIME TO BRING IT
TOGETHER.
TO THE FRYER.
WE'RE GONNA FRY
THE DOG?
FRY IT UP.
CHILI WE MADE EARLIER.
ME LIKEY.
DON'T GO SKIMPY ON THE CHILI.
(clearing throat)
(grunts)
CHEESE SAUCE.
ALL RIGHT.
FRIED APPLEWOOD-SMOKED BACON.
IT'S NOT JUST BACON,
IT'S FRIED BACON.
FRIED BACON, RIGHT.
SOME OF OUR BLUE CHEESE SLAW,
CRISPY ONIONS,
AND THAT'S
THE FRANK CUDA DOG.
DO I HAVE ANY? HUH?
NO. NOT AT ALL.
I LIKE THE DOG. I MEAN,
YOU GOTTA START OFF
WITH A REALLY GOOD DOG
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
THE CHILI'S GREAT.
THE CHILE WORKS PERFECT.
THANK YOU.
THE CRUNCHY ONIONS,
OF COURSE--FANTASTIC.
THE SLAW IS NICE
AND COOL.
MAN, THAT'S
A RIGHTEOUS DOG, DUDE.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB, PERRY.
(woman)
A FRANK CUDA.
THANK YOU.
MESSY BUT GOOD.
FRANKIE VALLI UP.
AND THESE DOGS
ARE ALMOST AS ICONIC
AS PERRY.
LOOK AT THAT GUY.
YEAH, A LOT
THINNER THEN.
PERRY HASN'T JUST MADE GOOD
WITH HOT DOGS.
THERE'S A WHOLE LOT MORE
TO THIS MENU.
YOU CAN GET ANYTHING--
SALADS, SANDWICHES, TACOS.
SWEET TEA-MARINATED
PORK CHOP?
AWESOME.
I THINK IT MAY BE THE BEST
SANDWICH I EVER PUT IN MY FACE.
WHAT'S NEXT
ON THE ADVENTURE?
WE'RE MAKING RED-EYE GRAVY
MAYONNAISE
TO GO ON OUR FRIED
PORK CHOP SANDWICH.
RED-EYE GRAVY.
NOW JUST SO YOU UNDERSTAND,
ALTHOUGH I DO LOOK
LIKE I'M FULL CALI,
MY MOM WAS
FROM NORTH CAROLINA.
RED-EYE GRAVY
IS LIKE A RELIGION.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
COUNTRY HAM...
THAT'S
A COUNTRY-DISIAC.
BROWN SUGAR, GARLIC,
SOME ARBOL CHILIES,
LITTLE MEXICAN CHILIES,
STRONG BLACK COFFEE.
SO WE'RE GONNA LET THIS
COOK DOWN, LET IT REDUCE.
WE, UM, TAKE
THE HAND BLENDER
WE'RE GONNA PURéE THE HAM
INTO THE SAUCE?
WE ARE.
(blender buzzes)
ALL RIGHT.
WHISK UP THE, UH,
RED-EYE GRAVY.
RED-EYE GRAVY
INTO THE MAYONNAISE.
LET IT CHILL.
READY TO SMEAR.
SO A LITTLE
PORK LOIN HERE.
TAKE THE CAP OFF OF IT.
THEN PUT IT IN THE MARINADE.
AND THE SWEET TEA--
THIS IS LIKE SWEET TEA
YOU DRINK?
SWEET TEA YOU DRINK.
HOW LONG DO WE
LET IT MARINATE?
6 TO 12 HOURS,
SO WE COULD DO IT OVERNIGHT,
AND IT WOULD BE BETTER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SEASONED BREADER
FOR THE, UH,
FRIED PORK CHOP SANDWICH.
OKAY.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
CORNMEAL,
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
AND SOME THYME.
AND WE'LL TAKE IT
THROUGH THE PROCESS HERE--
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR...
INTO THE BUTTERMILK,
THEN INTO THE DREDGE,
INTO THE FRYER...
INTO THE FRYER.
AND THEN WE BUILD
THE SANDWICH.
WE DO. TOAST THE BUN
FOR THE PORK CHOP,
RED-EYE GRAVY MAYONNAISE
AND A GOOD HELPING OF IT,
LETTUCE.
ALL RIGHT, SOUNDS LIKE
THE PORK'S DONE.
YEP. PORK CHOP.
TOMATO.
WHAT'S IT CALLED?
SWEET TEA-MARINATED
FRIED PORK CHOP SANDWICH.
THE PORK--COOKED PERFECTLY.
NOT SWEET--
IT'S NOT SWEET IN ANY WAY.
RIGHT.
I GOTTA SAY THE RED-EYE GRAVY
MAYONNAISE IS THE BOMB.
IT DOESN'T TASTE
A TON LIKE COFFEE.
YOU GET THE FATTINESS
OF THE MAYO.
IT'S JUICY.
IT'S GOT RICH FLAVOR.
AND WHAT I THINK IS REALLY COOL
ABOUT IT IS YOU'RE NOT A CHEF.
NO. NO, DON'T
CLAIM TO BE.
YOU'RE JUST A--
YOU'RE JUST A DUDE
THAT LOVES GOOD FOOD.
YEP. JUST WANTED
TO BRING
SOMETHING DIFFERENT
TO SUMMERVILLE.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SWEET TEA-MARINATED
PORK CHOP.
(man) IT'S A LITTLE MESSY,
BUT VERY GOOD.
(Guy) NOW WHAT DO YOU THINK?
HE DRAGS YOU OUT FOR DINNER,
AND HE TAKES YOU
TO A HOT DOG JOINT?
WE LOVE IT.
YOU ARE A HERO
IN THIS COMMUNITY.
SUMMERVILLE'S LUCKY
TO HAVE YOU.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE YOU COMIN'.
NICE TO MEET
YOU, PERRY.
YOU'RE AN AWESOME
GUY, MAN.
YES, SIR. THANK YOU.
UP NEXT,
IT'S BIZARRO WORLD.
IF YOU'RE LOOKIN'
FOR A SOUTHERN FIX,
THAT'S THE WAY TO GO
RIGHT THERE.
WE GOT FRIED CHICKEN
AND PEACH COBBLER
IN NEW YORK CITY.
I'M TELLING YOUR FRIENDS
BACK IN TEXAS.
YOU SEE IT EVERY DAY.
THAT'S IT. I AM OUT!
WONDER WHERE I'D LEFT MY BIKE.
SO HERE I AM IN THE EAST VILLAGE
OF MANHATTAN.
NOW DOWN IN THESE PARTS,
YOU CAN FIND JUST ABOUT
ANY KIND OF FOOD.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN' INDIAN,
ITALIAN, CHINESE, MEDITERRANEAN.
BUT WHEN I FIND OUT THAT THERE'S
A JOINT THAT'S SERVING UP
A MEAT AND TWO, YOU KNOW,
A TRADITIONAL SOUTHERN STYLE OF
SERVICE, I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS MAMA'S FOOD SHOP.
IN NEW YORK, YOU CAN GET
ALMOST ANY KIND OF FOOD
AT ANY TIME OF DAY,
BUT MAMA'S IS THE ONLY PLACE YOU
CAN GET A REAL HOME-COOKED MEAL.
FEELS LIKE A LITTLE OASIS
AWAY FROM THE CITY.
THIS RIGHT HERE--IF YOU
JUST DRUG ME OUT OF A CAR
AND YOU WALKED ME UP HERE,
I WOULD SAY I'M IN NEW ORLEANS.
FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
FRIED CHICKEN
OR THE MAC & CHEESE.
PEOPLE GET INTO FIGHTS
OVER WHAT'S BETTER.
WHEN YOU CAN'T HAVE
YOUR MOTHER'S COOKING,
COME TO MAMA'S.
(man) THERE'S
YOUR FRIED CHICKEN.
AND HOME COOKIN' IS WHAT
JEREMIAH CLANCY WAS LOOKING FOR
WHEN HE DISCOVERED THE JOINT
BACK IN COLLEGE.
I WAS AT N.Y.U.,
I USED TO EAT HERE A LOT.
HE MUST HAVE RUN UP
A KILLER TAB,
'CAUSE IN '06,
HE BOUGHT THE JOINT,
HIRING TEXAN SCOTT MORRIS
TO DO THE COOKING.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN MANHATTAN?
JUST LUCKY.
HOW'D YOU GET
THE JOB HERE?
JUST LUCKY.
I GUESS.
YEAH.
I GUESS IT HAD SOMETHING TO DO
WITH HIS SOUTHERN
BACKGROUND, TOO.
TWO MINUTES
ON FRIED CHICKEN, JEREMIAH.
WHAT SCOTT AND I ARE TRYING TO
DO IS MAKE THIS PERFECTION UNION
BETWEEN COMFORT FOOD
AND SOUTHERN FOOD.
I DON'T THINK THE SOUTH
CAN OWN FRIED CHICKEN.
SO THEY'RE CRANKING OUT
THEIR OWN HOME-COOKED VERSION,
MADE TO ORDER.
I'M A FRIED CHICKEN FREAK.
RIGHT NOW THIS IS MY FAVORITE.
THIS THE BOMB
FRIED CHICKEN.
IT IS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING THE MARINADE
FOR THIS FRIED CHICKEN.
OKAY, WELL, WALK US
THROUGH IT, MAN.
FIRST WE'RE GOING IN
WITH GARLIC, ONIONS.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A PURéE OF THIS?
YES.
(whistles)
THEN WE'RE LOOKING
FOR VINEGAR.
LOOSEN IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
LET THAT HANG OUT FOR A SECOND,
LET IT SPLATTER ON YOU.
THAT'S PART OF THE JOB.
YEAH.
THIS IS COUNTRY CAMO.
WHEN I KNOW THAT I'M GOING TO A
JOINT THAT SERVES MEAT AND TWO.
YEAH.
I WORE THIS, 'CAUSE I CAN GET,
LIKE, SOME GREENS HERE,
AND FRIED CHICKEN UP IN THERE,
AND YOU WOULDN'T BE ABLE--
YOU WON'T EVEN BE
ABLE TO TELL.
NOBODY.
TAKE THIS GUY,
WE'RE GOING STRAIGHT IN.
SO LIBERAL AMOUNTS
OF KOSHER SALT.
YES.
WHOSE RECIPE?
THIS IS, UH, JUST
A MAMA'S RECIPE. 15 YEARS.
IS THAT FRESH CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER?
IT IS.
NICE.
PAPRIKA.
SMOKED?
JUST REGULAR. LEMONS.
YOU GUYS GO THROUGH
SOME ROSEMARY, HUH?
YES, SIR.
OKAY, A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA GLOVE
IT UP NOW AND MIX.
RUB-A-DUB-DUB,
PUTTING ON THE GLOVES.
HOW LONG WILL THIS
AMOUNT OF CHICKEN LAST?
NOT VERY LONG,
THE WAY WE GO THROUGH IT.
WE USUALLY GO THROUGH ABOUT
TWO TO THREE CASES A DAY.
THAT'S 600 PIECES
OF CHICKEN A DAY?
ALMOST, YEAH.
OKAY, YOU'VE MASSAGED IT IN,
HOW LONG'S THE MARINADE GOING?
24 HOURS.
SO CHICKEN'S MARINATED,
TRANSFERRED INTO ANOTHER TUB,
NOW IT'S READY TO GO,
AND WE'RE GONNA BUILD A DREDGE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, SO ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
DIG IT.
DRIED ROSEMARY.
YOU'RE GONNA LEAVE THE ROSEMARY
IN BIG OL' CHUNKS LIKE THAT?
ABSOLUTELY.
THYME.
PINCH OF SALT.
THAT'S A HANDFUL.
YEAH.
LITTLE CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE, MAN.
DREDGE IT AND FRY IT. ONE OF
THOSE GUYS, ONE OF THOSE GUYS,
ONE OF THESE GUYS.
INTO THE FRYER.
FRA-ER.
YOU CALL IT FRA-ER?
FRYER.
I'M TELLING YOUR FRIENDS
BACK IN TEXAS.
LET ME SEE YOUR COWBOY BOOT.
CLOGS? NO WAY. I'M OUTTA HERE.
HOW LONG'S THE CHICKEN
GONNA TAKE?
17 MINUTES.
WE READY TO ROCK?
LET'S DO IT.
FIVE, FOUR, THREE,
TWO, ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
OOH, LOOK AT THAT.
WHAT DO YOU PREFER?
ALL OF IT.
OH, YEAH.
MIGHT AS WELL.
THAT'S ABOUT AS SOUTHERN
AS IT GETS RIGHT THERE.
THE BREAST IS SUPER TENDER, NOT
TOO MUCH BREADING, NICE FLAVOR,
SUPER-CRISPY SKIN. THAT'S,
LIKE, WHAT YOU LIKE ON TURKEY.
THAT'S TASTY.
THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT RIGHT.
IF YOU'RE CRUISING
THROUGH THESE PARTS
AND YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A SOUTHERN FIX,
I MEAN, THAT'S THE WAY
TO GO RIGHT THERE.
JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
YEAH?
YOU THE MAN.
IT'S INCREDIBLE. THE INSIDE
IS SO JUICY AND TENDER.
IT'S GOT ROSEMARY ON THE CRUST,
WHICH IS VERY UNIQUE.
AND IT STAYS NICE AND CRISPY.
THE KEY TO A GOOD FRIED CHICKEN.
IT'S HUGE PORTIONS OF DELICIOUS
MEAT AND SOME DELICIOUS SIDES,
AND THAT'S THE PERFECT
THING RIGHT THERE.
FRIED CHICKEN ROCKED.
DUDE, YOU CANNOT HAVE
ANYTHING ELSE UP YOUR SLEEVE.
OH, YEAH, HE DOES.
IT'S A PEACH COBBLER.
IT'S LIKE BREAKFAST
AND DESSERT ALL IN ONE.
IT IS INCREDIBLE.
YOU GONNA DO IT UP
RIGHT?
OH, YEAH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
HEY, AIN'T NOTHIN'
IN THERE YET. YET.
THIS DUDE SAYS HE'S GONNA
DELIVER SOME MEAN PEACH COBBLER.
WE'RE AT MAMA'S FOOD SHOP IN
THE EAST VILLAGE IN MANHATTAN.
NOW THIS IS
MEAN COBBLER?
YEAH.
SOUNDS LIKE A TIGER.
ALL RIGHT, DUDE,
HOW WE DOING IT?
PEACHES FIRST.
SO PEACHES. NEXT UP?
LITTLE BROWN SUGAR.
IF IT'LL COME OUT.
TALK NICE TO IT.
PLEASE COME OUT,
BROWN SUGAR.
CINNA-MINA-MINA-MINA.
CINNAMON.
WOW, THIS IS
AN INTERESTING ONE.
EVERYBODY, LET'S PLAY A GAME.
GUESS AT HOME--
WHAT IS HE PUTTING IN NEXT?
MARTHA IN OMAHA,
YOU GOT IT RIGHT--GINGER!
THAT'S RIGHT.
GONNA PUT SOME BUTTER IN.
OKAY, NOW MIX IT UP.
THEN WE'LL THROW THE DISH
INTO THE OVEN. WHAT TEMP?
350,
ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
DIG IT.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
WE'RE GONNA GET SOME
COBBLER TOP GOING.
WE'RE GETTING
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
SUGAR, BAKING POWDER.
LET'S GIVE IT
A LITTLE WHISK.
THAT'S IT!
I AM OUT.
THAT ENDS THE SHOW. GOOD NIGHT,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
A LITTLE WHISK.
THAT'S IT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
WAITING FOR THAT ONE?
LITTLE BUTTER, TOO.
EGG AND MILK.
YOU BREAK OUT THE LITTLE WHISK,
AND NOW I'M YOUR SOUS-CHEF?
WHAT HAPPENED?
SO THIS MIXTURE'S TOGETHER.
DON'T WANT
TO WORK IT TOO MUCH.
DON'T WANT TO BREAK DOWN
THE BUTTER. NOW WE LOOK GOOD.
NOW WE PULL OUT THE PEACHES
THAT HAVE HAD A CHANCE TO COOK,
CARAMELIZE THOSE DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN JUST THROW ON
SOME GLOBULES.
GLOBULES.
YOU JUST CAN'T PUT IT
ALL ON TOP.
OTHERWISE, YOU GOT TOO MUCH
STEAM COMING THROUGH,
AND THESE WON'T CRISP UP
THE WAY YOU WANT.
YOU'VE GOT A LOT OF MOISTURE
COMING OUT OF THERE,
SO YOU GOTTA JUST
GIVE IT SOME PATCHES
SO YOU CAN RELEASE
THE STEAM.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT'S THE SEASON
ON THIS?
CINNAMON. LITTLE SPRINKLE.
BACK IN THE OVEN,
HOW LONG?
ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, CHEF, WE READY?
WE'RE READY.
FANTASTIC.
LOOKS AWESOME.
SERVE IT UP.
COBBLER CRUNCH
RIGHT UP TOP.
THOSE PEACHES...
STILL HAVE TEXTURE.
STILL A LITTLE BITE TO 'EM.
NOT OVERSWEET.
STILL TASTE THE PEACH. KEY.
NICE LIGHT CRUST.
MAN, WHAT A NICE
SOUTHERN TREAT
ALL THE WAY OUT HERE ON
THE EAST VILLAGE OF MANHATTAN.
YOU DELIVERED ON THE NAME.
NICE JOB, CHEF.
LITTLE PIECE OF HEAVEN.
YOU GOT THAT RIGHT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY,
THERE'S FUNKY JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL LOOK FOR YOU NEXT TIME ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LIKE A ROLLER DERBY
OF FLAVOR IN MY MOUTH.
HE'S UP AGAINST
THE BOARDS.
YEAH, ELBOW.