HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
HOLY SCHNIKE!
WE'RE CRUISING DOWN
THE ROAD LESS TRAVELED
AND EATIN'
OUTSIDE OF THE BOX.
NOW WHAT'S IN THAT ROOM
OVER THERE?
(laughing)
OH, WE DON'T GO
BACK THERE.
(laughing)
YOU SON OF A...
IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND...
MONEY.
MY MAN DUFF HOOKS ME UP
WITH A FUNKY PIZZA PARLOR...
(laughter)
THIS IS THE JOINT.
JOE SQUARED.
RUNNIN' CIRCLES
AROUND RAVIOLI...
I'M NOT MAD AT THAT.
AND SQUARIN' UP ON THE PIE.
CRAZY GOOD!
IN DALLAS, TEXAS...
ALBONDIGAS SOUP.
(imitating Travis Bickle)
YOU TALKIN' TO ME?
THE DEEP ELLUM SPOT...
(lips smacking)
TURNING THE TABLES
ON TEX-MEX.
THE MEXICAN SIDE OF IT
FIRST?
YES.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND IN SANTA BARBARA,
CALIFORNIA,
THE FAMILY-RUN JOINT
WITH A MILLION-DOLLAR STORY...
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
(laughter)
AND A KILLER TWIST ON TURKEY.
IT'S LIKE
A TURKEY DINNER... CAKE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
(bell dinging)
HERE WE ARE IN BALTIMORE
FOR ANOTHER EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IT'S GONNA BE OFF THE HOOK!
(stifled laughing)
DUFF...
WHAT? WHAT? LOOK. I HAVE--
DUFF, I SAID
YOU COULD DRIVE THE CAR.
I DON'T KNOW, THE--
THE W--THE HAIR
AND THE--AND THE GLASSES.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE'RE IN DUFF'S HOMETOWN.
(laughing)
THIS IS JOE SQUARED.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
GET OFF MY BIKE.
YOU'RE CRA-- (laughing)
(laughing)
(laughter)
YOU CAN'T FIND ANYTHING
MORE BALTIMORE,
AND BETTER FOOD
THAN YOU'RE GONNA FIND
HERE AT JOE SQUARED PIZZA.
AND A FLAG PIZZA FOR YOU.
OOH!
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS THE JOINT.
JOE SQUARED.
AMAZING ATMOSPHERE AND PEOPLE,
AND THEN YOU HAVE GREAT FOOD.
AVOCADO RISOTTO.
YOU KINDA PUT YOURSELF
IN JOE'S HANDS.
ORDER UP, BAKED CLAM!
HAD YOU OWNED
YOUR OWN RESTAURANT BEFORE?
NO, NEVER, NEVER.
'CAUSE I'VE ALWAYS
WORKED IN RESTAURANTS.
AND IN 2005,
HE OPENED THIS JOINT
AND STARTED DOING THINGS
HIS WAY.
JOE'S PERSONALITY REALLY DOES
HAVE AN INFLUENCE ON HERE,
'CAUSE IT'S KINDA QUIRKY,
IT'S KINDA UNIQUE.
FROM THE SHAPE OF HIS PIES...
IT'S SQUARE.
SQUARE--SQUARE PULLS IT OFF.
MM-HMM.
TO WHATEVER HE'S PUTTING
ON TOP...
THEY'RE SO FRESH AND SO GOOD,
ESPECIALLY BECAUSE A LOT OF THEM
ARE COMING FROM THE GARDEN
RIGHT UPSTAIRS.
BARBECUE CHICKEN PIZZA.
I DESCRIBE IT
AS A GREAT PIZZA PLACE.
BUT IT'S SO MUCH MORE.
PASTAS, SANDWICHES, SUBS, UH,
FRIED RAVIOLIS.
(Duff) WHAT?
DAMN STRAIGHT.
LET'S SEE THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
AND BY "RIGHT," JOE MEANS
SCRATCH-MADE PASTA DOUGH.
FIRST UP?
COOL.
SO, WE, UH--
IS THAT SEMOLINA?
THAT'S SEMOLINA. HOLLOW IT OUT--
A LITTLE HOLE IN THERE.
DROP IN SOME, UH,
WHOLE EGGS
AND THEN SOME JUST
STRAIGHT EGG YOLK.
THROW THE RICOTTA DOWN
IN THE MIDDLE.
SALT--WHITE. PEPPER.
AND WE'RE JUST GOING TO,
UH, MIX THAT UP.
DON'T WANNA WORK IT TOO MUCH.
WELL, I DON'T WANNA
OVER-KNEAD IT, YOU KNOW?
SO MIX THIS TOGETHER,
BALL IT UP, WRAP IT.
LET IT REST. FIRST IN?
GROUND BEEF. LET IT
BROWN UP A LITTLE BIT.
STRAIN IT ALL,
GET ALL THE EXTRA FAT OFF.
GROUND SALAMI.
AH, THIS MAKES IT
EVEN EASIER.
OH, YEAH.
MMM.
NOW THROW SOME ONIONS
DOWN ON THE PAN.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTÉ
THOSE UP A LITTLE BIT.
(laughing)
THROW IN THE GARLIC.
LOOK AT THAT.
HE MOVES IT AWAY.
GONNA ADD IN THE GROUND BEEF,
WHAT'S LEFT
OF THE GROUND SALAMI.
(laughter)
IS THIS LIKE KEEP AWAY
FROM DUFF RIGHT NOW?
(laughter)
RICOTTA. DEMI-GLASE.
OH, NICE!
MMM.
OREGANO.
ROSEMARY, THYME.
WE GROW THIS UPSTAIRS
ON THE ROOF, TOO.
ON THE ROOF. NOW WHAT'S
IN THAT ROOM OVER THERE?
(laughing)
OH, WE DON'T GO
BACK THERE.
(laughing)
YOU SON OF A...
(laughter)
DAMN!
THEN JUST BRING IT DOWN.
EVERYTHING'S COOKED ALREADY.
YOU CAN TRY IT NOW
IF YOU WANT.
(laughs)
MMM! AH, THAT IS GOOD, HUH?
THAT'S AWESOME.
SO NOW WE LET IT
COOL DOWN,
FILL SOME RAVIOLIS.
RIGHT.
SO JUST THE RIGHT KIND
OF PIECE
THAT WE'RE GONNA START
RUNNING THROUGH THE SHEETER.
RIGHT. LIGHTLY FLOURED.
PASS IT THROUGH.
WE'LL FOLD HER OVER.
PASS HER THROUGH.
THAT'S THAT.
GRAB OUR MOLDS.
(Guy) NOW HE'S MAKING
THE INDENTIONS INTO THE MOLDS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE FILLING IN.
(singsongy) HMM, HMM, HMM.
I'M GETTING IT.
SO FAR, SO GOOD?
EGG WASH IN BETWEEN.
CLEAN 'EM UP.
TAKE ANOTHER SHEET OF DOUGH,
POP IT OVER TOP.
TAKE THE ROLLING PIN,
GO RIGHT OVER IT.
I'LL CUT 'EM ON THE MOLDS.
THROW THOSE ON A SHEET PAN.
THROW 'EM IN THE FREEZER.
SO THE RAVS ARE NOW FROZEN.
FINAL STEP?
EGGS, MILK, BLACK PEPPER,
SALT.
MIX THAT UP.
SO NOW INTO OUR FLOUR MIX
WE'RE PUTTING
A LITTLE ONION POWDER
AND GARLIC POWDER.
NOW MIX THAT UP REAL QUICK.
AND TO OUR BREAD CRUMBS,
A LITTLE ITALIAN SEASONING--
OREGANO, THYME, ROSEMARY,
MARJORAM.
SHAKE THAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
GET THESE INTO THE EGG WASH.
SO MOVE 'EM INTO THERE.
IT'S NOT HIS FIRST RODEO.
NO.
NOW THEY'RE COATING
WITH THE EGG WASH.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO INTO
THE BREAD CRUMBS,
INTO THE PANKO?
RIGHT.
COMPLETELY COAT IT.
FREEZE IT AGAIN.
RIGHT.
WE REALLY BIND THAT CRUST
TO THE RAVIOLI.
NOW WE'LL GET A UNIFORM COOK
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
CORRECT.
THEY'RE ABOUT READY.
(whistles)
QUESTION I'VE BEEN ASKING
THE WHOLE TIME,
WHICH I'M NOT GONNA REALLY
CRITIQUE THIS
BEFORE I'VE HAD A BITE
OF IT--
IF THERE'S ENOUGH
SALAMI IN THIS.
LOOKED LIKE YOU WERE
A LITTLE SHY.
(laughs)
I'M NOT MAD AT THAT.
I LIKE DIPPING
IN THE MARINARA.
YOU GET ACIDIC,
THEN YOU GET CRUNCH,
THEN YOU GET TO THE SALAMI
AND THE MEAT ON THE INSIDE.
LOT OF TIMES YOU GET
FRIED RAVIOLI
AND IT'S SO MUCH DOUGH.
YOU HAVE TO MAKE IT
WITH A THIN DOUGH
'CAUSE YOU'RE GONNA
BREAD IT.
YOU'RE DOIN' IT REAL DEAL
BACK HERE, MAN.
WELL DONE. THANK YOU.
NICE JOB ON THE RAV.
HEY, THANKS, MAN.
AWESOME.
FRIED RAVIOLI
FOR THE TABLE.
ALL THE FLAVORS THAT YOU EXPECT
A GREAT RAVIOLI TO HAVE.
SO SORRY. YOU GOTTA GO.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'LL CATCH YOU OUT IN--
IN A LITTLE BIT.
(laughs) OH, MAN, LOOK,
I'M GETTIN'...
IT'S REALLY A GOOD TIME.
THE BOOT, BUT--
TRY THE--
YOU OWE ME
A FREE PIZZA!
(laughs)
ORDER UP, VEGAN PIZZA!
HE HAS A REALLY GOOD BUZZ
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
JOE GETS PROPS FOR THAT, TOO.
HE'S JUST SUCH A LEADER
IN THE COMMUNITY,
AND REALLY REVITALIZED
NORTH AVENUE.
JOE'S KIND OF THE MAD SCIENTIST
OF PIZZA.
BACON CLAM!
COME BACK.
THE MAN'S ON FIRE.
(laughs)
AT LEAST THE OVEN IS.
SEE YOU IN A BIT.
(laughs)
♪♪
THERE'S JUST SOMETHING
A LITTLE DIFFERENT
ABOUT THE PIZZA AT JOE SQUARED
IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND.
YOU CAN TELL
EVEN FROM LOOKING AT THE PIZZA.
YEAH. IT'S GOT FOUR CORNERS.
ALL THE PIZZAS ARE SQUARE?
ALL THE PIZZAS ARE SQUARE.
AND A NORMAL PIZZA OVEN
DOESN'T CUT IT, EITHER.
THE COAL-FIRED OVEN.
YOU GO COAL-FIRED
'CAUSE IT CAN BURN HOTTER.
800 TO 900 DEGREES
ON THE FLOOR,
1,500 TO 2,000
POPPIN' OFF THE DOUGH.
HOLY SCHNIKE! DUDE!
DUDE, THAT IS THE HOTTEST
OVEN I'VE EVER BEEN BY.
WHAT MAKES THE FOOD
SO SPECIAL HERE
IS IT STARTS
WITH THE INGREDIENTS.
'CAUSE JOE WILL PUT
JUST ABOUT ANYTHING ON A PIZZA,
FROM HERBS HE GROWS
ON THE ROOF...
ARUGULA.
TO SPAGHETTI AND MEATBALLS.
CHICKEN, CORN, AND APPLE
ON PIZZA.
AND THIS ONE...
ORDER UP, BACON CLAM!
(chuckling) JOE'S TAKE
ON SURF-AND-TURF.
BUT IT'S A SOUVENIR
FROM ITALY
THAT'S A GAME CHANGER
FOR THIS PIE.
I WAS IN FLORENCE
IN THE CENTRAL MARKET THERE,
AND SOMEBODY WAS SELLING
A BUNCH OF OLD YEASTS.
AND THAT'S WHERE I PICKED UP
THIS STARTER.
THE STARTER, IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE, UH,
A BIT OVER 200 YEARS OLD
FROM THE ISLAND OF ISCHIA
OFF THE COAST OF, UH, NAPLES.
SMELLS AWESOME.
I LOVE IT.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
ADD IN SOME FLOUR.
AND YOUR WATER.
AND YOU'RE JUST MIXING IT UP.
I'M JUST TRYING TO GET
THE YEAST TO SPREAD.
BUILDING A BIGGER STARTER.
EXACTLY.
HIGH FIVE, MAN.
THAT'S AWE--
YEAH, BUDDY. JUST GET--
OH, DUDE.
(laughter)
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO
LEAVE SOMEBODY HANGING.
ALL RIGHT, COOL.
WHOA! ALL RIGHT.
SO THIS IS YESTERDAY.
SO NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
NOW WE POUR IT
IN THE MACHINE. (groans)
THEN WE'RE JUST PUTTING
EQUAL PARTS
OF FLOUR AND WATER
IN THERE.
WHAT TYPE OF FLOUR?
CAPUTO DOUBLE "O."
DOUBLE "O"?
(clicks tongue)
UH-HUH.
SO WE'LL MIX THIS THROUGH.
JUST GONNA SPREAD THE YEAST.
IT'LL START RISING
BACK UP, YOU KNOW.
GOT IT.
GET IT NICE AND SPONGY.
HOW LONG?
UM, PROBABLY ABOUT
TWO, TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
NOW WE'RE MAKING
OUR SPONGE INTO DOUGH.
NOW YOU ADD IN
ANOTHER 2/3 OF FLOUR.
1 CUP OF SALT.
OKAY.
WE GET HER STARTED
TO INCORPORATE A LITTLE BIT.
ONCE IT STARTS GRIPPING A LITTLE
BIT, THEN WE ADD THE OIL.
THE OIL SO IT PULLS
AWAY FROM THE BOWL.
UH-HUH.
YOU LET THAT PROOF
FOR ANOTHER TWO HOURS?
ABOUT TWO HOURS OR SO.
MAN, WHAT A LABOR OF LOVE
THIS IS.
THIS IS GOING
FOR WHAT PIZZA?
BACON AND CLAM IS THE ONE
WE'LL BE COOKING TODAY.
(inhales)
MY MIDDLE NAME
IS BACON AND CLAM.
MY PARENTS WERE HIPPIES.
HIPPIES DON'T EAT BACON.
THEY DID--MINE DID.
OH, MAN.
YEAH, RIGHT OFF THE HOOF.
NOW YOU'RE IN THE KNOW.
OKAY, JOE, THIS IS IT?
YES. GRAB
YOUR CHUNK OF DOUGH.
MOIST.
IN AND OUT A LITTLE BIT.
OPPOSITE DIRECTION?
EXACTLY.
I DON'T THINK THESE ARE GONNA
COME OUT COOKIE-CUTTER UNIFORM.
OH, NO.
OKAY, LET'S SEE IT.
SEMOLINA.
NOW WE'RE CUTTIN' IT.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S NOT EVEN
IN ROUND FORM.
NO.
BACK IN THE--
WE'LL PUT IT
OFF TO THE SIDE.
UH, WE'LL END UP, UH,
MAKING A NEW BATCH OF STARTER
OUT OF IT EVENTUALLY.
OKAY.
NO WASTE.
THIS LITTLE SCREEN--
THAT JUST A MARK?
WE ALSO SERVE THEM
ON THESE SCREENS, TOO,
ON TOP OF THE PLATE.
SEE, WE COOK IT SO HOT,
THERE'S SO MUCH MOISTURE
TRAPPED IN THE DOUGH,
IF I PUT IT ON A PLATE,
IT SOGS UP QUICK.
IT'S GONNA STEAM RIGHT OUT.
YOUR ROASTED GARLIC.
WE GO THIN ON IT
'CAUSE IT'S STRONG.
FROZEN CLAM.
FROZEN CLAMS.
THAT'S A LOT OF CLAMS.
CHOP YOUR BACON DOWN.
WE'RE PRETTY GENEROUS
ABOUT SUCH THINGS.
BOCCONCINI?
THAT'S A CILLENCINI.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
A BOCCONCINI AND A CILLENCINI?
CILLENCINI'S CHERRY SIZED.
THE BOCCONCINI'S
A LITTLE BIT BIGGER.
I SHOULD TASTE THAT
AND JUST MAKE SURE.
(laughs)
EXACTLY RIGHT. THAT IS
A CILLENCINI.
SLICED VIDALIA ONION.
ASIAGO.
HOW LONG
WE GOING DOWN FOR?
GOING DOWN
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE.
THIS WE GOTTA RUN
A STOPWATCH ON.
REGISTERING RIGHT NOW
AT ABOUT 900 ON THE DECK
AND 1,200 ON THE DOME?
PROBABLY CLOSER TO 1,500
OFF THAT DOME.
FIVE, FOUR, THREE,
TWO, ONE.
THAT IS SMOKIN' HOT.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SPIN.
(whistles)
FINAL CRISP ON THE BOTTOM.
NICE!
LOOK AT THAT.
A LITTLE BIT OF OREGANO.
OLIVE OIL.
I LOVE THE SCREEN IDEA.
MMM.
WOW. CRUST IS COOKED OFF
PERFECT.
MMM. NICE TEXTURE.
NICE CHEW.
THIS IS A LOT OF CLAMS,
GREAT GARLIC SAUCE.
MMM.
FRESH HERB AT THE END
FINISHES IT.
DUDE! CRAZY GOOD.
MMM.
I'LL GIVE YOU
THE HIGH FIVE NOW.
OH, MAN!
NICELY DONE. MONEY.
I GOT A BACON AND CLAM PIZZA.
I THINK THE FACT
THAT IT'S SQUARE--
I GET MORE--MORE CRISPY CRUST.
CLAM FLAVOR
GOES WITH THE CREAM SAUCE.
PASTA IN CLAM SAUCE.
HE TAKES A LOT OF PRIDE IN
THE FOOD THAT HE PUTS OUT HERE.
I JUST ENJOY THE CREATIVITY
THAT'S HERE.
(laughter)
JOE SQUARED. PIZZA JOINT.
LOT OF LIVE MUSIC.
A COOL BAR.
YOU'RE DISGUISING
JUST HOW...
CULINARY SOLID
YOU ARE BACK HERE.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU.
(whooshes)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED DOWN
TO DEEP ELLUM IN DALLAS...
YES!
WHERE TEX-MEX
IS DOING A BACKFLIP
INTO MEX-TEX.
MOUTH IS STARTING TO WATER
ALREADY.
♪♪
YOU KNOW, WHENEVER I COME
INTO THE GREATER DALLAS AREA,
I'M ALWAYS THINKING
ABOUT TEX-MEX.
WELL, THEN I HEAR ABOUT THIS
JOINT DOWN HERE IN DEEP ELLUM,
AND THEY SAY, "NO,
WE'RE NOT TEX-MEX.
WE'RE MEX-TEX. WE'LL PUT
A LITTLE FLIP ON IT."
A LITTLE FLIP ON IT? I GOTTA
TRY SOME OF THOSE TACOS...
HERE AT THIS JOINT--
PEPE'S & MITO'S.
(indistinct conversations)
ALBONDIGAS SOUP.
CAN'T GET ANY BETTER.
IT'S JUST FABULOUS.
(sizzling)
'CAUSE AFTER SPENDING YEARS
WORKING
IN TEX-MEX RESTAURANTS...
I'VE BEEN IN THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS SINCE 11 YEARS OLD.
OWNER PEDRO ROJAS GOT A PLACE
WHERE HE COULD PUT
HIS MEXICAN ROOTS FIRST.
PEOPLE IN THIS AREA
CALL IT TEX-MEX.
YOU SAY, NO, YOU'RE...
MEX-TEX.
THE MEXICAN SIDE OF IT
FIRST?
YES.
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT COMES
TO HIS MOM'S
HOMEMADE MEXICAN MEATBALL SOUP.
ALBONDIGAS IS THE SOUP.
YEAH. WHAT SHE SAID.
CALDO DE ALBONDIGAS.
CALDO... ALBONDIGAS.
DE ALBONDIGAS.
THE MEATBALL SOUP.
OKAY.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF CANOLA OIL.
THAT'S ONIONS.
BELL PEPPERS, TOMATOES.
WE GOT SOME MINCED GARLIC.
BLACK PEPPER.
GROUND CUMIN. CUMINO.
SOME WATER.
LET IT SIT
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
YOU ADD SOME CHICKEN BASE
IN THERE.
YOU BRING THAT TO A BOIL.
YOU ADD SOME FRESH CILANTRO
TO IT
AND SIMMER FOR ABOUT
20 MINUTES.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME--
LIKE A MEXICAN ROBERT DE NIRO.
PICADILLO.
DON'T YOU THINK?
(imitates Travis Bickle)
YOU TALKIN' TO ME?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
PICADILLO FOR THE ALBONDIGAS.
OKAY.
FOR THE ALBONDIGAS--
LIKE THE MEATBALLS.
GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF MARGARINE.
WE USE EXTRA-LEAN
GROUND BEEF.
WELL, IT IS
SWIMSUIT SEASON.
JUST GONNA BROWN THAT
FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
CARROTS.
SOME STEAMED POTATOES.
I USED TO HAVE THOSE
MASHED UP BY NANNY.
(lips smacking)
WE GOT DICED ONIONS.
AND BLACK PEPPER,
CUMINO.
AND SOME GRANULATED GARLIC.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
DICED POBLANO PEPPERS.
AND A LITTLE MORE CILANTRO?
AND A LITTLE FRESH
CILANTRO IN THERE.
SO THAT'S IT? WE TAKE THIS...
(mouth full)
MAKE THE MEATBALL.
YOU'RE GONNA BEAT AN EGG.
(scraping)
SO THIS IS GONNA
ALL COOK TOGETHER.
WE'LL ADD EGG TO BIND IT,
AND THAT WILL MAKE THE...
ALBAGON--ABAGON--AGABA--
ALBONDIGAS.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S AL BUNDY'S BROTHER
FROM GUATEMALA.
HEY!
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE PICADILLO.
AND THEN LAYER IT
TO THE GRILL.
(sizzling)
BROTH.
(mouth full) AND YOU JUST FLOAT
THOSE RIGHT IN THERE LIKE THAT?
FLOAT THEM ON THERE.
OH, THAT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
FRESH CILANTRO ON TOP
AS A GARNISH.
AND THEY COME
WITH THE FLOUR TORTILLAS.
YOU GUYS MAKE 'EM
YOURSELF?
HANDMADE.
WE DON'T COOK 'EM
UNTIL WE GET AN ORDER.
MMM! THIS TEXTURE'S
OUTRAGEOUS.
DELICIOUS.
THAT SOUP IS GANGSTER.
(mouth full)
MMM! THE BROTH IS SO RICH,
FLAVORFUL WITH THE PEPPERS
AND ONIONS AND THE TOMATOES.
MMM! DYNAMITE.
THE TORTILLAS AND THE MEATBALLS
MADE TO ORDER--
IT'S KILLER, MAN. BOMB!
YOUR CALDO DE ALBONDIGAS.
AND YOU DIDN'T LIKE
THE SOUP?
YOU HAVEN'T EATEN THE PORCELAIN
OFF THE BOWL--
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S THE REAL-DEAL MEXICAN FOOD?
OH, YEAH.
WITH ALL THE REAL-DEAL
MEXICAN STAPLES,
FROM HOMEMADE PORK TAMALES
TO BEEF ENCHILADAS...
THESE ARE THE BEST ENCHILADAS
HERE IN DALLAS.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
BEEF TACOS NORTEÑOS.
TO A MEXICAN FAVORITE
I GO BANANAS FOR--
AND YOU KNOW
BANANAS IS A GOOD THING.
TACOS NORTEÑOS, READY TO GO.
MY WIFE LOOKS AT OUR ACCOUNT
AND SAYS EVERY MONTH,
"WH-WHAT'S GOING ON?"
YOU HAVING AN AFFAIR?
WITH THE TACOS NORTEÑOS.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, PEP.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
TACOS NORTEÑOS.
TACOS OF THE NORTH?
NORTHERN STYLE.
OKAY. LET'S MOVE.
YOU JUST WANNA TRIM
ALL THE FAT OFF OF IT.
MMM. THAT'S NICE.
BOTTOM SIRLOIN.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
FILET IT.
NOW HOW WE GONNA COOK THIS?
WE'RE JUST GONNA GRILL IT
ON THE CHARBROILER.
(sizzling)
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME
CHIPOTLE SAUCE NOW.
LET'S HIT IT.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME TOMATOES.
RED ONIONS.
AND SOME DRIED CHIPOTLES.
OKAY, AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME WHITE ZINFANDEL.
WHICH YOU DON'T SEE
GETTING COOKED WITH OFTEN.
CABERNET.
THEN WE'RE GONNA SIMMER THAT
FOR TWO HOURS.
COOK DOWN, REDUCE IT
ALL THE WAY DOWN
TO ABOUT 10% LIQUID.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA BLEND
THAT WITH SOME CREAM.
A LITTLE HEAVY CREAM?
(whirring)
SO WE RUN THIS A FEW BATCHES,
THEN WHAT'S NEXT?
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT IT
BACK ON THE STOVE,
ADD SOME BUTTER TO IT
AND CHICKEN BASE, AND LET IT--
AND THAT'LL FINISH IT OUT?
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT
ON THE TACOS NORTEÑOS?
WE ARE DEFINITELY GONNA
PUT IT ON THE TACOS NORTEÑOS.
MOUTH IS STARTING
TO WATER ALREADY.
WE GOT THE GRILLED...
BOTTOM SKIRT.
A LITTLE BIT OF--
WHICH IS GREAT BY ITSELF.
A LITTLE BIT OF MARGARINE
IN THERE.
(sizzling)
AND WE ADD SOME
PICO DE GALLO TO IT.
CHIPOTLE SAUCE TO IT.
(sizzling)
AND THIS FILLING'S MADE
EVERY TIME?
EVERY TIME.
OKAY, SO WE GOT
THE MINI CORN TORTILLAS.
THEY'RE--THEY'RE GONNA GO ON
THE GRILL FOR ABOUT A MINUTE.
THEN THEY'RE READY--
READY TO PLATE.
PLATE THE TORTILLAS
ON THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
FRESH CILANTRO ON TOP.
TACOS NORTEÑOS.
(mouth full) MMM! OH, MY GOSH!
THAT'S OUTSTANDING!
I LIKE EVERYTHING ABOUT IT.
THE MEAT'S FANTASTIC.
YOU GET A NICE CHAR TO IT.
REAL NICE TENDER,
YOU KNOW, CHEW.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
I'M SO CLOSE TO MEXICO,
AND I'M IN THE LAND
OF TEX-MEX,
ALTHOUGH THIS IS MEX-TEX.
IT NEEDS TO BE THE REAL DEAL.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
HE'S CHANGED MY LIFE.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
IT IS RIDICULOUS.
I LOVE THIS PLACE.
THE BEST.
TACOS NORTEÑOS--
THE BOMB.
AND THE SOUP?
ALBONDIGAS?
AL BUNDY THAT LIVES
DOWN IN GUATEMALA?
MONEY.
COMING UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA,
WHERE A MOM-AND-POP JOINT
IS LIVING THE DREAM...
THAT IS SUCH
AN INSPIRING STORY.
AND TURNING TURKEY
INTO A FRITTER.
WINNER, WINNER, TURKEY DINNER.
(laughs)
♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN SANTA BARBARA,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE CITIES
IN THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA,
JUST ABOUT A BLOCK
OFF OF STATE STREET,
THE MAIN DRAG,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT I HEAR HAS A STORY
THAT'S ALMOST AS GREAT
AS THEIR FOOD.
THIS IS SAVOY CAFE & DELI.
(woman) START WITH
THE BALSAMIC CHICKEN.
(indistinct conversations)
(man) CHICKEN MARSALA, PLEASE.
IT'S VERY CONVENIENT,
BUT IN A DELI ENVIRONMENT.
BEEF STROGANOFF.
YOU WANT A SIDE WITH THAT?
ALWAYS FRESH, ALWAYS GOOD.
ENJOY YOUR MEAL, SIR.
THANK YOU.
THE OWNERS
ARE PAUL AND KATHY SHIELDS.
THEY'RE JUST LOCAL
HOMEGROWN FOLKS
THAT ARE LIVING THEIR PASSION.
IT'S A STORY
YOU HEAR EVERY DAY.
PAUL AND KATHY OPENED
THEIR DREAM JOINT IN '05,
AND THE PLACE GOES NUTS,
RIGHT?
UH, NOT EXACTLY.
YEAH, WE ACTUALLY
TANKED.
YEAH. YEAH.
BANKRUPT IN 2008.
WE LOST IT.
LOST OUR HOUSE.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
(laughs)
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
WE TOOK A JOB
AS A JANITOR.
THE CHURCH WE ATTEND,
THEY GAVE US A JOB.
THEY GAVE US A HOUSE
TO LIVE IN.
SOMEBODY CAME IN
AND--AND OPERATED IT
FOR ABOUT A YEAR AND HALF,
AND THEN SOLD IT BACK TO ME--
FINANCED, THE WHOLE DEAL--
AND HE SAID,
"YOU JUST PAY ME
A LITTLE BIT EVERY MONTH."
HE JUST WANTED TO SEE ME
BACK IN THE STORE.
MAN, BRING A TEAR TO MY EYE.
SERIOUSLY.
OH. YES.
CURRY CHICKEN SALAD
QUINOA.
GOOD THINGS HAPPENING
TO GOOD PEOPLE--
YOU GOTTA DIG IT.
AND THIS SECOND CHANCE
HAS KATHY RULING
THE DESSERT CASE
AND PAUL ROCKIN' HIS KITCHEN.
YOU'RE SCRATCH-MAKIN'
EVERYTHING?
UH-HUH.
YEAH.
SCRATCH-MAKIN' DISHES
LIKE THE STUFFED
CHICKEN BREAST,
CHICKEN MARSALA,
AND THEIR MASH-UP ON A FRITTER.
TURKEY PASILLA FRITTER.
THE TURKEY PASILLA FRITTER
IS FANTASTIC.
IT HAS PASILLA CHILIS IN IT
THAT GIVE IT A NICE WARMTH.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
TURKEY PASILLA FRITTERS.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE GONNA ROAST OFF
A NATURAL FREE-RANGE TURKEY.
SO WE TAKE MIREPOIX--
ROUGH CHOP.
MAKE A NICE BED OUT OF THAT.
AND WE'RE GONNA PLOP THIS BIRD
RIGHT INTO THAT.
A LITTLE SEA SALT.
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT
A LITTLE BATH IN HERE--WATER.
JUST SO WHEN THAT FAT
DRIPS OFF, IT DOESN'T BURN.
CORRECT.
DIG IT. WHAT TEMP?
350.
FOR?
3 HOURS, 45 MINUTES
TO 4 HOURS.
THERE'S A BEAUTY, HUH?
YEAH, IT CAME OUT NICE.
WHAT WE DO NOW--
BREAK IT UP.
TAKE THE SKIN OFF.
SKIN OFF.
(laughs)
MMM.
FREE-RANGE TURKEY--
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
(mouth full) KEEP GOING,
OR I'LL KEEP EATING.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
SO WE HAVE THE CORNUCOPIA
OF, UH--OF INGREDIENTS HERE.
SHREDDED TURKEY.
DARK MEAT, WHITE MEAT.
PASILLA CHILI.
OHH! LOVE PASILLAS.
THESE WERE PICKED LOCALLY
ON A FARM.
FRESH JALAPEÑO.
PICKLED JALAPEÑO.
A LITTLE BIT OF VINEGAR?
YOU LIKE THAT?
YEAH. YEAH.
SHREDDED RUSSET POTATO.
FRESH CILANTRO. ORGANIC.
SLICED RED ONIONS.
(chuckles)
SO THEN WE THROW IN,
UH, EGGS.
KINDA MIX 'EM UP IN HERE.
FROM THE CHICKEN YOU KNOW?
(chuckling)
FROM THE CHICKEN WE KNOW.
WE HAVE PROFILES
ON ALL OF OUR CHICKENS.
YES, WE DO.
MAYONNAISE.
A LITTLE SALT.
A LITTLE A.P.?
A LITTLE A.P.
BIND IT UP WITH THE EGGS.
FORM THESE INTO A BALL?
SO SEAR 'EM OFF
SO WE HOLD 'EM TOGETHER...
(sizzling)
THEN FINISH 'EM
IN THE OVEN.
WOW! BRING IT!
ALL RIGHT.
QUINOA SALAD.
QUINOA MANGO SALAD.
HEALTHY.
LOOK AT THAT!
YEAH.
THAT HAS AWESOME TEXTURE.
I LOVE ROASTING PASILLAS,
AND I WAS WONDERING,
WHEN YOU DIDN'T DO THAT,
WAS I GONNA GET THAT
ROASTED PASILLA FLAVOR?
(mouth full) BUT AS LONG
AS THAT COOKED IN THE OVEN
REALLY GAVE IT SOME OF THAT
ROASTED FLAVOR.
YOU SMELL THE ROAST TURKEY.
A LITTLE BITE OF THE JALAPEÑO.
(mouth full)
YOU GET THE CREAMINESS.
THE--THE PEPPERS AND THE ONIONS
HAVE COOKED DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S LIKE A...
(mouth full)
TURKEY DINNER... CAKE.
MMM!
WE'LL CHANGE THE NAME
TO TURKEY DINNER CAKE.
WINNER, WINNER, TURKEY DINNER.
(laughs)
CAN I GET THE, UH,
TURKEY PASILLA?
(woman) CHICKEN MARSALA.
YOU'RE AWESOME PEOPLE.
I AM JU--THAT IS SUCH
AN INSPIRING STORY.
(speaks indistinctly)
YOU'RE DEFINITELY
A STRONG FAMILY,
PUTTING THE BOYS
THROUGH THAT.
I WONDERED WHY THEY
WERE SUCH NICE KIDS.
(laughs)
LET ME BRING THESE
CHARACTERS IN HERE.
THIS ELI, NOAH, ADAM,
AND LEROY.
(laughter)
IT'S NOT LEROY, IS IT?
NO. JACK.
JACK. I KNEW IT!
I WAS SO CLOSE.
SO, LISTEN, NEXT TIME
WE COME IN HERE,
I BETTER SEE YOU GUYS
IN HERE BUSSING TABLES.
LET'S WAVE!
(laughter)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(laughing)
(Duff laughing)
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S WORSE.
IT'S, LIKE, SO AWFUL!
(crew laughing)
IT'S KIND OF THE MOST
UNAPPETIZING... COMBO.
(woman speaking indistinctly)
(laughter)