HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
RAWR!
(Guy) THIS TRIP,
CHECK IT TWICE...
WOW.
'CAUSE NOTHIN' IS QUITE
WHAT IT SEEMS.
(mallet thuds)
(man) IT WORKS OUT.
IT SEEMS SO WRONG,
BUT IT JUST FEELS SO RIGHT.
IN CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA...
YOU'RE LIVIN' ON THE EDGE.
THE LATE NIGHT,
EARLY MORNIN' JOINT...
THEY STAY OPEN
TILL 4:00 IN THE MORNING.
SERVIN' UP BREAKFAST
FOR DINNER...
CHICKEN & WAFFLES.
OR IS IT DINNER FOR BREAKFAST?
(mouth full) THAT IS GONNA
SCREW UP PEOPLE'S BREAKFASTS
THE REST OF THEIR LIFE.
(chuckles)
(laughs)
OUTSIDE BALTIMORE...
(makes beeping sound)
WHERE'S THE LID?
HE JUST WENT INTO ROBOT.
THE CLASSIC '50s DINER
THAT'S A FRONT...
DUDE.
FOR SIGNATURE GREEK DISHES.
OPA!
(laughs)
AND IN OXNARD, CALIFORNIA...
I LIKE WHERE THIS IS GOING.
A TRIPLE-THREAT SPOT...
(chuckles) SNAP.
SCRATCH-MAKIN' BURGERS...
MMM. MMM!
THAT ARE MORE
THAN MEETS THE EYE.
(laughs)
WAS IT THAT GOOD?
IT WAS OUTSTANDING!
(laughs)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
IN CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA,
ON THE VERY BUSY
SAVANNAH HIGHWAY
JUST A FEW MILES OUT OF DOWNTOWN
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE A COUPLE HAS BEEN WORKING
FOR YEARS
TO PUT THIS DINER TOGETHER.
THEY GOT IT ALL COMPLETED.
ALL THEY NEEDED TO DO WAS
COME UP WITH A NAME.
(chuckles) OH, AND DID THEY HAVE
SOME DOOZIES. LET'S SEE.
THEY HAD "THE RUSTY BUCKET,"
"THE AMERICAN U.S.A. DINER,"
OR MY PERSONAL FAVORITE,
"DEXTER'S HOUSE OF GRAVY."
WELL, THEY FINALLY FIGURED OUT
WHAT THEY'RE GONNA NAME IT,
AND HERE IT IS--
THE EARLY BIRD DINER.
ORDER UP. OPEN FACED TURKEY.
SOUTHERN COMFORT FOOD.
BOWL O'GRITS.
(man)
I THINK I PROBABLY EAT HERE
ALMOST MORE THAN I EAT AT HOME.
I'M NORMALLY HERE
EARLY IN THE MORNING
AND LATE AT NIGHT.
AND THIS DUDE'S GOT COMPANY.
WE COME TO THE EARLY BIRD DINER
USUALLY AROUND 2:00 OR 3:00
IN THE MORNING,
NOT NECESSARILY FOR BREAKFAST.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SINCE '08,
OWNERS DEXTER HAIGLER...
ORDER UP. SHRIMP AND GRITS.
AND NICOLE MORRIS...
CHICKEN & WAFFLES.
HAVE BEEN KEEPING
THEIR FRYER FRYING LATE...
(chuckles) AND I MEAN LATE.
BISCUITS AND GRAVY BACON.
FRIDAY AND SATURDAY,
WE GO 8:00 A.M.
TILL 4:00 IN THE MORNING.
EVENTUALLY, I THINK
WE DO WANT TO DO 24 HOURS.
WE'RE BUILDING TOWARDS THAT.
THAT'S CALLED CRAZY.
(laughs)
YEAH, RIGHT?
GOOD THING
THEY'VE GOT ONE DISH
THAT'S WORKIN'
ROUND THE CLOCK.
CHICKEN & WAFFLES.
PROBABLY MY FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU--
THE CRISPINESS OF THE CHICKEN,
THE FLUFFINESS OF THE WAFFLE.
THE BEST THING ABOUT IT
IS THE COMBINATION
OF THE HONEY MUSTARD
AND THE SYRUP.
THAT CHICKEN & WAFFLES--
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
IT SEEMS SO WRONG,
BUT IT JUST--
IT WORKS OUT.
IT SEEMS SO WRONG,
BUT IT JUST FEELS SO RIGHT.
(man, deep voice)
♪ OOH, BABY ♪
(man) ♪ COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON, COME ON ♪
OKAY. ROLL.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, FIRST WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR MARINADE
FOR OUR CHICKEN.
BUTTERMILK?
YEAH. BLACKENING SEASONING,
AND THEN A TINY BIT
OF HONEY.
ALL RIGHT. WE'RE GONNA POUND
AND MARINATE THE CHICKEN.
(thuds)
LET ME THROW THAT
IN THE BAG,
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR MARINADE.
LET THAT GO FOR ABOUT A DAY?
MM-HMM.
NEXT UP, THE DREDGE?
YEAH, WE'RE JUST GONNA
GRIND UP
SOME PECANS
FOR OUR PECAN FLOUR.
I ADD JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF FLOUR TO IT.
(whirs)
NEXT, WE GOT
OUR, UH, ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR FRESH GROUND PECANS.
BLACKENED SEASONING FIRST.
THEN SOME
FRESH GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
SALT.
YEAH.
THAT'S PROBABLY GOOD THERE.
THIS IS THE CHICKEN
THAT WE MARINATED OVERNIGHT.
WHEN I DO THIS,
I TRY TO KEEP ONE HAND DRY
AND ONE HAND WET.
IF YOU DON'T, UH, DO THAT,
YOU'LL MAKE YOURSELF
INCREDIBLE HULK FINGERS.
(chuckles) YEAH, EXACTLY.
RAWR!
NOW--
YOU GOT 'EM READY TO GO
IN THE FRYER?
YEP.
(sizzling)
SO WE GOT THE CHICKEN DONE.
NOW WE'RE INTO MAKING
THE WAFFLES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'M GONNA START
WITH A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE BAKING POWDER,
FRESH GROUND CINNAMON.
UH, THAT'S
OUR ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
MAKE SURE THAT
THEY'RE THOROUGHLY MIXED.
MM-HMM. I'LL MAKE MY WET--
WHOLE MILK...
OKAY.
EGGS, BUTTER,
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF MAPLE SYRUP.
I'M SLOWLY ADDING
MY DRY MIX.
MAN, I GET THE CINNAMON
AND THE MAPLE SYRUP
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
IT'S WAFFLES GONE WILD.
IT IS. (chuckles)
JUST ENOUGH
SO IT COVERS THE BOTTOM.
THAT MUCH? SERIOUSLY?
WELL, I MEAN, I WASTE
A LITTLE BIT ON THE SIDE,
BUT I FEEL LIKE--
YOU'RE LIVING ON THE EDGE,
AREN'T YA?
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO IT COMES OUT, UH, NICE OUT
OF THE WAFFLE MAKER,
BUT WE LIKE IT TO BE REAL CRISPY
ON THE OUTSIDE, SO--
SO YOU DRY IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT MORE.
YEAH.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TOAST
THE WAFFLE A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT. WE START
WITH OUR HONEY MUSTARD,
AND IT'S JUST
A SPICY BROWN MUSTARD,
A LITTLE SYRUP.
WAFFLE ON THERE.
THEN CHICKEN.
A LITTLE BIT OF
EXTRA HONEY MUSTARD ON TOP.
A LITTLE BIT MORE
ON THE WAFFLE.
YOU GET THE SAVORY CHICKEN
AND THE SWEET WAFFLE
AND EAT 'EM TOGETHER?
WE'VE SEEN PEOPLE
MAKE SANDWICHES OUT OF IT.
CHICKEN'S SUPER TENDER,
A LITTLE BIT OF BREADING.
THERE'S
A NICE LITTLE BIT OF HEAT
COMING OFF
FROM THE MUSTARD.
GET SOME OF THE SWEETNESS
OF THE SYRUP.
(mouth full)
THE SAVORY, THE SWEET,
THE CRUNCHY, THE SALTY--
I MEAN, YOU JUST GOT
ALL KINDS OF THINGS
GOING ON HERE.
THAT IS GONNA SCREW UP
PEOPLE'S BREAKFASTS...
(chuckles)
THE REST OF THEIR LIFE.
(laughs)
AWESOME.
THANKS, MAN.
OHH.
(indistinct conversations)
CHICKEN & WAFFLES.
OOH, WOW.
(Guy) HOW IS IT?
EXCELLENT. YOU WANT A TASTE?
OH, YOU KNOW WHAT? I--
AS YOU CAN TELL,
I'VE ALREADY HAD, LIKE...
(laughs)
(both laugh)
TWO ORDERS.
UM, THE HONEY MUSTARD SAUCE
IS AMAZING.
THAT MIXED WITH MAPLE SYRUP
IS THE BOMB, ISN'T IT?
IT SURE IS.
ORDER UP. MESS FOR TABLE ONE.
HOW'D YOU GUYS FINALLY COME
TO THE IDEA OF OPENING A DINER?
YOU KNOW, WE WANTED TO HAVE
A PLACE WHERE WE COULD DO
WHATEVER WE WANT.
WE'RE JUST TRYING TO MAKE
SIMPLE FOOD REALLY WELL.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
THANK YOU.
HERE "SIMPLE" MEANS
SHRIMP AND GRITS,
BLACKENED GREEN TOMATO MELT,
AND THIS SCRATCH-MADE
TOP SELLER.
FRIED PORK CHOP.
THANK YOU.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
(woman)
THE PORK CHOP IS SO GOOD.
I LOVE THE SWEET AND SPICY JELLY
WITH IT.
I GET IT ON EVERYTHING THAT I
GET HERE AT THE DINER. (laughs)
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
UH, PEPPER JELLY
FOR THE PORK CHOP.
AND WHAT DO WE GET
THE PECTIN OUT OF?
IT COMES FROM APPLES.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT JELLY,
WHAT'S GONNA JELLIFY IT--
SO THIS IS ACTUALLY APPLE?
YEAH.
YEAH, IT'S MADE FROM APPLES.
APPLE. GOOD. COOL.
START WITH
OUR, UH, PINEAPPLE JUICE,
PEPPER VINEGAR.
PEPPER VINEGAR?
WE TAKE APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
WE CHOP UP, UH, HOT CHILIES
AND PUT IT IN THERE.
OVER TIME, IT GETS
SPICIER AND SPICIER.
SHOW-OFF.
SUGAR,
FIRE-ROASTED BELL PEPPERS.
NOW I'M GONNA PUREE
THE PEPPERS.
(whirs)
I'M GONNA ADD MY PECTIN.
THERE WE GO.
SO STIR THAT IN.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
MY FROZEN PEPPERS.
THESE ARE GONNA BE WHAT ARE
GONNA ACTUALLY COOL THIS DOWN?
YEAH.
LOOKS LIKE
A BUNCH OF BELL PEPPERS--
RED, YELLOW.
AND, UH, A LITTLE BIT
OF JALAPEÑO.
THIS SHOULD GIVE US
A NICE, SPICY RED PEPPER JELLY.
MM-HMM.
IT'S GOTTA COOL OVERNIGHT.
ALL RIGHT. THIS IS, UH, THIS IS
WHAT MY PORK CHOPS LOOK LIKE
WHEN THEY GET HERE.
THE CHINE BONE HAS NOT BEEN
TAKEN OUT?
NO. I ACTUALLY LIKE
THE EXTRA BONE ON THERE
'CAUSE WE MAKE
OUR OWN PORK STOCK.
SO IF YOU'RE GONNA BUY IT,
BUY IT WITH THE BONE
BECAUSE THE FLAVOR'S
IN THE BONE.
YOU WON'T SEE THAT
EVERY DAY.
LET'S TAKE THE CHINE OFF.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA POUND THIS DOWN,
TENDERIZE IT UP.
SORRY. (laughs)
NOW THE DREDGE?
YES, SIR.
GOT A.P. FLOUR,
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACKENING,
A LITTLE FRESH GROUND BLACK,
AND A LITTLE KOSHER SALT.
SO WE'RE GONNA FLOUR,
BUTTERMILK, FLOUR.
THEN IT'S IN THE FRYER.
CANOLA OIL AT 350?
YES, SIR.
RIGHT ON.
PORK CHOP'S READY.
PORK CHOP MAXIMUS.
FINISH THIS UP WITH
OUR FIRE-ROASTED PEPPER JELLY,
AND THAT'S
WITH A LITTLE MAC AND CHEESE
AND SOME
FRESH COLLARD GREENS THERE.
I NEED TO GET
SOME PEPPER JELLY TO GO, MAN.
LOOK AT THAT.
(utensils clink)
(mouth full)
IT'S REAL SIMPLE.
THE CHOP IS NOT OVER-SEASONED,
NOT OVER-FRIED, NOT GREASY.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CRUNCH.
WITH THAT PEPPER JELLY,
REAL PEPPER FLAVOR,
DUDE, THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
FRIED CHOP.
GOT PEPPER JELLY RIGHT HERE.
ORDER UP. FRIED PORK CHOP.
WELL, WHAT DID YOU HAVE?
OH, THE, UH,
FRIED PORK CHOP.
HOW WAS IT?
IT'S MOSTLY GONE,
BUT DELICIOUS.
(man) YOU GOT THIS GREAT CRUNCH
IN THE CRUST,
BUT THE PORK CHOP IS
STILL MOIST,
AND THE PEPPER JELLY GIVES IT
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEET, SPICY KICK TO IT
RIGHT AT THE END.
CHICKEN & WAFFLES.
OH.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
EARLY BIRD IN ONE WORD--
SATISFYING.
IT IS PROBABLY ONE OF THE MOST
SATISFYING MEALS I'VE HAD.
(Guy) FUN PLACE.
I LIKE THE ATTITUDE.
(Nicole) MM-HMM.
I LIKE THE ENERGY.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME, GUYS.
IT WAS FUN.
YEAH, THANKS
FOR BEING HERE, MAN.
APPRECIATE IT. THANKS.
REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
OH, THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
(laughs)
WE'RE HEADED OUTSIDE BALTIMORE
FOR YIA YIA'S HOME COOKIN'.
I AM THE DOLMADES MAN.
THAT'S AS GREEK AS IT GETS.
I COULD GET IN TROUBLE
WITH THESE.
(laughs)
♪♪
YEAH, I THINK
WE FIGURED IT OUT BY NOW.
SOME OF THE GREATEST DINERS
WE'VE SEEN ON TRIPLE "D"
ARE OWNED BY GREEK FAMILIES.
I MEAN, IT'S THE PASSION
FOR FOOD, THE STRONG FAMILY,
AND FUELED BY TRADITION,
AND THIS ONE'S NO DIFFERENT.
HERE WE ARE
IN DUNDALK, MARYLAND,
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF BALTIMORE.
THIS IS THE BOULEVARD DINER.
SPINACH PIE UP.
GOT BROWN GRAVY ON THAT.
MEAT LOAF TOWER.
IT'S LIKE A LANDMARK HERE.
THIS IS THE GO-TO JOINT?
OH, YEAH.
SOUR BEEF AND DUMPLINGS.
PERFECTED OVER YEARS BY
OWNER MARC TSAKIRIS'S GRANDDAD.
YOUR GRANDFATHER HAS A DINER
BACK IN THE DAY.
IT WAS CALLED THE...
RIGHT.
HOUSE OF NEPTUNE.
SEAFOOD DINER?
CRAB HOUSE.
SOME OF
THE OLD-SCHOOL MENU ITEMS...
YEAH.
THAT HE DID THERE,
YOU GUYS STILL DO HERE.
OH, YEAH. YES.
BROILED CRABCAKES
IN THE WINDOW.
SO IT WAS AN EASY CHOICE
WHEN THE PRE-MED STUDENT GOT
A SHOT
AT RUNNING HIS OWN DINER...
SPINACH PIE UP.
(chuckles) ON--GET THIS--
THE SAME FAMILY LOT.
(Guy) THIS IS JUST PART
OF THE--YOUR FAMILY MAKEUP.
PART OF
MY FAMILY MAKEUP, YES.
WHAT'S THE FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
YIA YIA'S GRAPE LEAVES.
IT'S A, UH, RICE
AND A, UH, BEEF MIXTURE.
THE INGREDIENTS ARE GREAT.
(Marc) AND THAT MAKES 'EM
VERY SPECIAL.
"YIA YIA" IS "GRANDMA"?
YES.
IT'S MY GRANDMOTHER,
AND THESE ARE A FAMILY RECIPE
THAT COMES FROM GREECE.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY CALLED
"DOLMADES."
WE JUST CALL 'EM
STUFFED GRAPE LEAVES HERE.
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR GROUND PORK AND BEEF,
FRESH SCALLIONS, FRESH DILL.
(whistles) COPIOUS AMOUNTS
OF THAT, HUH?
YES. CHOPPED WHITE ONION...
(dish clatters)
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME GARLIC POWDER, SALT,
AND A LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HAVE
SOME RICE.
SANDS IN THE HOURGLASS.
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP.
MMM. I SMELL THAT DILL.
THAT'S AWESOME.
OKAY. RIGHT NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR TOMATO PUREE SAUCE,
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME BUTTER.
MELT THAT IN THERE.
WE ARE GONNA ADD OLIVE OIL.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME TOMATO PUREE.
COOK IT ALL THE WAY DOWN,
AND THIS ALL GOES IN WITH
YIA YIA'S GRAPE LEAF MIXTURE?
YES, SIR, AND WE'RE GONNA
DUMP THAT IN.
SMELL THE MAGIC IN THERE.
DID YOU PUT MAGIC
IN THERE, TOO?
THERE COULD BE A LITTLE BIT.
I DIDN'T EVEN HEAR IT.
SO NOW WE'VE GOT THIS
MIXED UP. NOW WHAT, HUH?
ROLL 'EM UP.
GRAPE LEAF.
TAKE THIS LITTLE STEM OFF
THE BACK HERE.
JUST GET A LITTLE PORTION ON,
AND WE ROLL THE BACK FIRST,
THEN THE SIDE,
AND THEN ALL THE WAY.
YOU GOT IT. YOURS IS A JUMBO,
BUT YOU'RE A NATURAL.
WHEN YOU WERE A KID
AND YOU WOULD GO
TO YOUR YIA YIA'S HOUSE,
SHE WOULD MAKE THESE?
SHE WOULD,
AND NOW EVERYBODY IN MY FAMILY
GETS ME TO MAKE 'EM FOR 'EM.
SO YOU'RE THE--YOU'RE
THE ONE THAT--
I AM THE DOLMADES MAN.
OKAY. NOW THIS INTO HERE?
YES, BUT FIRST
WE'RE GONNA LINE
THE BOTTOM OF THE PAN
WITH SOME GRAPE LEAVES ALSO.
OKAY.
AN OLD GREEK TRICK, I GUESS,
SO THAT WE DON'T BURN
THE BOTTOM PORTION
OF THE GRAPE LEAVES.
SO YOU CAN JUST STACK 'EM
ON TOP OF EACH OTHER?
WE'RE GONNA STACK 'EM NEATLY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA GO THIS WAY.
SO THEY'RE IN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME OLIVE OIL FIRST,
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
LEMON JUICE,
AND USUALLY WE USE
A WHOLE BOTTLE,
JUST BECAUSE THIS IS WHERE
ALL THE FLAVOR COMES FROM.
IT GETS SATURATED
INTO THE GRAPE LEAF,
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
AND WE'RE GONNA COVER THIS?
WHERE'S THE LID?
(makes beeping sound)
HE JUST WENT INTO ROBOT.
SO WE PUT THE PIE PAN DOWN,
AND THEN WE PUT THIS
TO WEIGH IT DOWN...
SO THAT...
AND THEN--
KEEPS PRESSURE
ON THE WHOLE MIX?
KEEPS THE PRESSURE ON IT
SO EVERYTHING DOESN'T
BLOW UP IN THERE,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR LID.
KEEPING ALL THE STEAM
INSIDE.
THAT'S IT.
WOW. THAT FITS SNUG.
OH, YES.
(man laughs)
(laughs)
I USE IT AS A SHIELD.
THEY'LL SIMMER PROBABLY
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
THEY ARE DONE.
WE USUALLY PUT FIVE OUT.
WE ALSO HAVE A SAUCE
WITH IT, TOO.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR CHICKEN STOCK DOWN.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT GO,
RUE TO THAT
AND, UH, RAW EGGS
AND A LITTLE LEMON.
OKAY.
AND THAT'S GONNA BE THE SAUCE
THAT WE'RE GONNA PUT--
THAT'S GONNA BE THE SAUCE
WE'RE GONNA PUT ON TOP
WHEN WE PRESENT THEM.
AWESOME.
AND THEN CRACKED PEPPER,
AND WE'RE SET.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
(mouth full)
DUDE, THAT IS KILLER.
THE GRAPE LEAF JUST REALLY
WRAPS AROUND IT NICE AND TIGHT.
I THINK PEOPLE LOOK AT IT
AND GO, "OOH, GRAPE LEAF.
I DON'T KNOW IF I WANT TO EAT
A GRAPE LEAF. I DON'T--"
THAT'S THE THING, YEAH.
IT'S TENDER. YOU GOT
THE LEMON JUICE EGGNOG SAUCE
THAT YOU PUT ON THERE.
(laughs)
YOU GOT THE TEXTURE
OF THE BEEF, THE RICE.
ALL THE FLAVORS LOCKED
RIGHT INSIDE.
RIGHT.
I COULD GET IN TROUBLE
WITH THESE.
(laughs)
OUTSTANDING.
YOUR YIA YIA SHOULD BE
VERY, VERY IMPRESSED WITH THAT.
I CAN SERIOUSLY--
I'LL HAVE THOSE TO GO.
GREAT.
NICE JOB.
(man) THE FILLING HAS TO BE
NICE AND MOIST.
NOT SOGGY.
EXACTLY.
I'VE HAD GRAPE LEAVES ELSEWHERE,
BUT THESE ARE THE BEST.
IT IS REAL DEAL FOOD.
OH, REAL DEAL.
UP NEXT...
(hums)
WE'RE BACK AT THE BOULEVARD...
HOLY PEPPER! HOW MUCH ARE
YOU PUTTING IN THERE?
(imitates Irish brogue)
IT'S MAGICAL.
FOR COMFORT FOOD...
THAT'S CRAZY. MMM.
(chuckles)
WITH A SPLIT PERSONALITY.
IT'S LIKE WON-SCHNITZELS.
RIGHT. (chuckles)
HOW ABOUT MISO-GERMAN?
WE'LL BE BACK
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
(lowered voice) OPA.
♪♪
FROM THE OUTSIDE,
THE BOULEVARD DINER
IN DUNDALK, MARYLAND,
IS THE DICTIONARY DEFINITION
FOR THE CLASSIC DINER,
BUT DON'T LET THE '50s FEEL
FOOL YA.
THEY'RE CRANKIN' OUT
REAL DEAL GREEK...
CHICKEN SOUVLAKI.
AND JUST ABOUT ANYTHING ELSE
THEY CAN COME UP WITH.
THE MENU HAS PRETTY MUCH GOT
EVERYTHING YOU WANT.
THIS IS A NOT A MENU.
THIS IS--THIS IS A BOOK.
IT'S LIKE A BOOK.
DUDE, IT'S ENORMOUS.
IT'S A SHIELD.
IT IS. (laughs)
IT'S A HAT.
IT'S WINGS. (laughs)
(man laughs)
IF YOU WANT VARIETY,
THIS IS THE PLACE
TO COME FOR IT.
MARC USUALLY MAKES
A COUPLE OF CRAZY CREATIONS.
I'D LEAN MORE TOWARDS
PSYCHOTIC.
(laughs)
THEY'VE GOT
THE BIG "A" SANDWICH--
6 POUNDS OF CORNED BEEF,
PIT BEEF, AND POT ROAST
THAT I CAN KINDA WRAP
MY HEAD AROUND.
DID YOU MODEL THIS
AFTER MY FAT FACE?
(woman laughs)
(laughs)
THE MEAT LOAF TOWER--
THAT GOES ALL JENGA
WITH STACKS OF MEAT LOAF,
MASHED POTATOES,
AND ONION RINGS JUST FOR KICKS.
OR THEIR TAKE
ON GERMAN-ASIAN FUSION...
SOUR BEEF AND DUMPLINGS.
(chuckles) WAIT. WAIT. WHAT?
TODAY WE'RE GONNA BE MAKING
SOUR BEEF AND DUMPLINGS.
TYPICALLY WHEN I THINK OF MEAT
AND I THINK OF SOUR,
NOT SO MUCH.
IT'S A GERMAN SPECIALTY,
AND WE JUST KIND OF ADAPTED IT
HERE AND DID OUR OWN THING.
OURS IS
A LITTLE SWEET AND SOUR.
SO IT'S CHINESE?
A LITTLE MIX
BETWEEN CHINESE/GERMAN.
IT'S LIKE WON-SCHNITZELS.
RIGHT. (laughs)
(Asian music playing)
WHAT ELSE COULD WE HAVE?
HOW ABOUT MISO-GERMAN?
(whispers) OHH.
OKAY, SO SOUR BEEF.
WE GOT A TOP ROUND.
WE CUBE THIS THIS SIZE HERE.
WE'RE GONNA SAUTÉ IT FIRST.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR BUTTER,
AND THEN ONCE THE BUTTER
MELTS A LITTLE,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR ONION AND CELERY.
SO NOW IN WITH THE BEEF?
YES. LET'S PUT THE BEEF IN.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
AND PEPPER--WE DO NEED
A LITTLE MORE PEPPER.
YOU--YOU PUT THAT ON
LIKE HARRY POTTER.
HOLY PEPPER! HOW MUCH ARE
YOU PUTTING IN THERE?
(imitates Irish brogue)
IT'S MAGICAL.
(normal voice) WE LIKE
TO GET IT GOING A LITTLE BIT,
BECAUSE THE FLAVORS
THAT ARE COMING LATER
ARE GONNA BE VERY DIFFERENT.
WHY DID YOU GO IRISH ON ME?
A LOT OF--SORRY.
SORRY. I JUST--
(man laughs)
I--WHEN I GET--I GET
EXCITED AND NERVOUS...
(chuckles)
IT'S A GERMAN DISH.
I JUST...
(chuckles) THAT'S TRUE.
I CAN'T DO GERMAN, THOUGH.
ALL THE OTHER ONES
I CAN KINDA DO, LIKE...
(Greek accent) A GREEK ONE,
YOU KNOW, LIKE--
YOU ARE GREEK.
I AM GREEK, YEAH.
OPA!
OKAY, SO NOW THE MEAT'S
BROWNED OFF,
COOKED DOWN WITH THE, UH,
THE CELERY AND THE ONIONS.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
BROWN SUGAR, WHITE SUGAR,
A GALLON OF VINEGAR,
AND WATER.
SO AFTER WE LET THIS BRAISE,
THIS, UH, IT'S GONNA REDUCE.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE ALSO GONNA NEED
TO TIE UP SOME PICKLING SPICE
AND THROW THAT IN WITH IT.
DROP THAT IN.
HOW LONG IS THAT
GONNA STAY IN?
THIS STAYS IN FOR THE DURATION
OF THE COOKING.
HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA GO?
TWO AND A HALF HOURS,
AND THEN, UH, WE'LL TAKE
THE PICKLING SPICE OUT
AND ADD
OUR SPECIAL INGREDIENT.
(hums)
(chuckles)
THIS IS
THE SECRET INGREDIENT?
THE SECRET INGREDIENT.
(crunches, mouth full)
GINGERSNAPS?
GINGERSNAPS. (chuckles)
SO NOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO IS
MAKE A GINGERSNAP PUDDING,
IN A SENSE.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE WATER,
LET IT SOAK FOR A LITTLE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA MAKE IT MUSH.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD 'EM IN
TO OUR ALREADY SIMMERED BEEF.
YOU KNOW, IT THICKENS IT
WITHOUT ADDING
ANY CORNSTARCH OR RUE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GIANT LADLE
OUR SOUR BEEF.
NOT SERIOUS. THAT MUCH?
OH, YEAH.
AND THEN
THESE ARE POTATO DUMPLINGS,
AND WE'RE SET.
WOW. THAT'S CRAZY.
(mouth full)
I'VE NEVER HAD SOUR BEEF.
I LOVE SOUR THINGS.
I LOVE VINEGAR,
AND THEN YOU TIGHTEN IT UP
WITH THE GINGERSNAPS,
AND YOU GET THAT LITTLE BITE
IN THERE...
AND THE DUMPLINGS,
AND IT DOES REALLY HAVE
THAT GERMAN FLAVOR
AND THAT GERMAN APPEAL TO IT.
I'D EAT THIS EVERY DAY.
(whispers) YEAH.
THIS IS
MY KIND OF COMFORT FOOD.
I HAD IT ON TUESDAY,
AND I'M HERE TODAY, SATURDAY,
EATING IT AGAIN.
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
COOL PLACE. YEAH, I SEE WHY
THE TRADITION'S GOING WELL.
YOU--YOU'RE ROCKIN' IT OUT.
YOU ARE DEFINITELY
A CHARACTER.
THANK YOU. (chuckles)
YOU ARE
THE QUINTESSENTIAL DINER DUDE.
"DINER DUDE"!
UP NEXT...
THE LAMB BURGER.
(chuckles)
AT A FUNKY NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
IN OXNARD, CALIFORNIA.
(imitating Julia Child)
OH, I'M GOING TO TOSS
THE VEGGIES NOW.
(laughs)
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN HISTORIC DOWNTOWN OXNARD,
RIGHT BETWEEN SANTA BARBARA
AND LOS ANGELES.
NOW THIS AREA IS KNOWN
FOR ITS BOMB AGRICULTURE,
ESPECIALLY THE STRAWBERRIES,
SO YOU GOTTA EXPECT
RESTAURANTS IN THIS AREA ARE
SERVIN' IT UP
FRESH AND HOMEMADE,
JUST LIKE THIS JOINT,
WHERE THEY'RE COOKIN' IT,
BAKIN' IT, AND BREWIN' IT.
THIS IS THE KITCHEN.
IT'S THE BEST THING YOU CAN FIND
NORTH OF LOS ANGELES.
ASIAN CHICKEN WRAP UP.
THE FOOD IS EXCELLENT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHETHER--
IF YOU'RE IN THE BAKERY,
IN THE BAR OR RESTAURANT,
IT ALWAYS FELT LIKE
YOU WERE AT HOME.
CLOSE TO HOME AS YOU CAN GET
WITHOUT BUSING THE TABLE.
EXCEPT WHEN THEY ASK YOU.
(laughs)
I THINK--I THINK
IT IS SOMETHING IN THE D.N.A.
NO DOUBT, 'CAUSE WHEN YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT
OWNER CATHIE MORENO'S FAMILY,
THE BIZ IS IN THE BLOOD.
(chuckles)
(Guy) SO YOUR MOM HAD
A RESTAURANT?
SHE DID.
YOUR SISTER?
YEP. THAT'S WHERE
IT ALL STARTED.
AND THIS--
AND IT ALL STARTED HERE
JUST OVER A YEAR AGO...
MEATLOAF SANDWICH,
TABLE SIX.
AFTER CATHIE WENT SEARCHING
FOR A WAY
TO EXPAND HER CATERING COMPANY.
I NEEDED A BIG KITCHEN,
AND THE RESTAURANT CAME WITH IT.
PACKAGE DEAL.
TURNED OUT THAT WAY
FOR CUSTOMERS, TOO...
HERE IS
YOUR MEATLOAF SANDWICH.
'CAUSE UNDER ONE ROOF,
YOU GOT A BAKERY, A BREWHOUSE,
AND A FULL-SERVICE KITCHEN
SERVING UP
SCRATCH-MADE FAVORITES
LIKE THE LAMB BURGER...
PLATING UP THE LAMB BURGER.
TOPPED
WITH A RED PEPPER RELISH.
LAMB BURGER UP.
(Guy)
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
ALL RIGHT. WE ARE MAKING
THE RED PEPPER RELISH
FOR OUR LAMB BURGER.
I DIG IT.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR OLIVE OIL,
DICED WHITE ONION,
DICED GARLIC,
DICED RED PEPPERS,
ORANGE PEPPER.
I LIKE WHERE THIS IS GOING.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS GO
FOR A MINUTE OR TWO.
OKAY.
SWEAT IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
BROWN SUGAR,
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
DRY MUSTARD POWDER,
AND SOME CAYENNE.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'LL LET THIS
ALL COOK DOWN, COOL IT DOWN,
AND THEN WE'LL SERVE THAT
ON THE LAMB BURGER.
CORRECT.
SMELLS GREAT.
OKAY, SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA
DO NOW?
WE ARE GOING TO START MAKING
OUR MIX FOR THE LAMB BURGER.
YOU SOUND LIKE
A NEWS REPORTER.
(laughing)
"AND NEXT UP,
THE LAMB BURGER."
(laughs) WE'RE CUTTING
THE LAMB BURGER WITH BEEF.
CORRECT.
WHY?
WE NEEDED THE BEEF IN THERE
TO GIVE IT SOME EXTRA FAT
AND JUICE.
WE MIGHT AS WELL BEEF IT UP.
(chuckles) SNAP.
FIRE IT UP.
ALL RIGHTY.
LET'S START
WITH OUR MINCED WHITE ONION,
FRESH MINT.
WOW, THAT MINT IS ROCKIN'.
DICED RED PEPPER.
(chuckles)
SOME CHOPPED GARLIC.
I'VE GOT
SOME GRANULATED GARLIC NOW,
CORIANDER, ALLSPICE,
BLACK PEPPER, CAYENNE.
A LITTLE CUMIN
AND SOME SALT. I DIG IT.
OKAY.
LIGHTLY TOSS IT THERE.
GIVE ME YOUR BEST JULIA CHILD
WHEN YOU DO THIS.
(high-pitched, nasal voice)
OH, I'M GOING TO TOSS
THE VEGGIES NOW.
(laughs)
WASN'T THAT GOOD? (laughs)
IT WAS OUTSTANDING.
(laughs)
WOW. THE GROUND LAMB.
GROUND BEEF.
FLIP IT AROUND.
IT SMELLS AWESOME.
(chuckles) YEAH, THAT MINT.
WHAT SIZE OUNCE PATTY ARE
WE GONNA MAKE?
A 6-OUNCE. OKAY, SO WE NEED
A LITTLE PIECE OF PLASTIC
TO PUT IN OUR SHAPER.
PUT THAT RIGHT IN THERE.
WRAP IT UP. READY TO GO.
THE BURGER'S HAD A CHANCE
TO MARRY SOME FLAVORS.
DO YOUR MAGIC.
ALL RIGHTY.
WE'RE GONNA START IT
ON THE FLATTOP.
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE SALT
AND PEPPER.
WE'RE READY TO FLIP.
NICE LITTLE CRUST ON THAT.
YEAH.
THIS HELPS TIGHTEN IT UP.
AND ALSO KEEPS MORE
OF THE JUICE IN,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA MOVE IT
TO THE CHAR GRILL.
OKAY. WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS ON?
OUR HOMEMADE BUN.
YOU MAKE THE BREAD HERE
AS WELL?
YEP.
YOU BAKE IT HERE FRESH?
WE DO.
EVERY DAY?
YEP.
ARE WE READY?
WE'RE READY,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH SOME
ROASTED RED PEPPER RELISH.
THIS IS HOW YOU'RE GOOD
TO GO RIGHT HERE?
THIS IS HOW WE'RE
GOOD TO GO.
(mouth full) MMM. MMM!
THIS IS RIGHTEOUS.
SO THE BEEF CUTS IT.
A GREAT BALANCE BETWEEN THE TWO.
REALLY LIKE GETTING
THE MINT. MMM.
BUT WHAT TIES IT ALL
TOGETHER IS THE RELISH.
YOU GET SOME OF THE SWEET
FROM THAT BROWN SUGAR,
THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND THE BELL PEPPER,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT ACID
FROM THE APPLE CIDER VINEGAR
COMING IN,
A TOUCH OF THAT MUSTARD.
MMM.
AND THEN THE KICKER
IS THE BUN.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOCKED THAT ONE OUT.
IT ROCKS.
(chuckles)
WHOO!
THE RELISH ON TOP--FABULOUS.
(man) IT'S A LITTLE SWEET
AND A LITTLE SPICY.
IT REALLY COMPLEMENTS
THE LAMB FLAVOR.
(man) HOMEMADE BUNS. LIKE--
(woman) YEAH.
SEE, THAT, TO ME, IS ONE
OF THE BIG KICKERS
RIGHT THERE.
YES.
(man) EVERYTHING'S HOMEMADE.
EVERYTHING I'VE EVER HAD
ON THE MENU HAS BEEN FANTASTIC.
(woman) WHEN PEOPLE FIND IT,
THEY SPREAD THE WORD.
GREAT REVIEWS FROM PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KEEP COMING BACK.
I'M VERY HAPPY.
WHAT A PERSONALITY, HUH?
COME FOR THE FOOD.
STAY FOR THE FLOOR SHOW.
(laughs)
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKIN'
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(Greek accent)
I AM GREEK, YEAH.
YOU PUT THE WINE IN,
AND YOU BURN YOUR ARM HAIRS
LIKE THIS LOOKING COOL.
(chuckles)
FLAMBÉ. FLAMBÉ.
LOOK AT ME, HUH?
(high-pitched voice, laughs)
YOU KNOW?
OPA!
(claps hands)
(chuckles)