HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
A EUROPEAN VACATION...
YES!
WITHOUT PULLING OUT
THE PASSPORT...
ANYBODY WHO
DOESN'T LIKE IT,
LET 'EM TALK
TO GUY, YOU KNOW?
IN NEW YORK CITY'S
EAST VILLAGE,
THE 103-YEAR-OLD
ITALIAN JOINT...
GIMME BACK THE MONEY!
STRAIGHT OUT
OF CENTRAL CASTING.
OH, OH, OH!
FEEL LIKE YOU'RE RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN OLD NEW YORK
MOB MOVIE?
AND IN
SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA...
OH!
A FISH AND CHIP SHOP...
MY FRIEND,
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
SERVIN' UP THE LINGO...
THAT WAS MONEY!
THE FLAVOR...
THE WHOLE EXPERIENCE
IS COMIN' BACK.
AND MY DEEPEST FEAR.
HAGGIS!
I'M SCARED.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN NEW YORK CITY.
LOVE COMING TO THIS PLACE.
I MEAN, THE OLD-SCHOOL
TRADITION,
ALL DIFFERENT KINDS OF FOOD--
ESPECIALLY SOME
OF MY FAVORITE ITALIAN.
NOW I'M IN THE EAST VILLAGE,
AND I HEAR THAT THERE'S
AN ITALIAN JOINT
THAT'S BEEN OPEN FOR 103 YEARS--
103 YEARS! I GOTTA SEE THIS.
THIS IS JOHN'S OF 12th.
VEAL MEATBALLS.
ONE OF THE BEST TRADITIONAL
ITALIAN FOODS IN NEW YORK.
BRUSCHETTA,
GETTING OUT.
WHENEVER
I'M IN THE MOOD
FOR ITALIAN,
THIS IS WHERE I'M COMING.
GOT A PAPPARDELLE,
HOMEMADE PAPPARDELLE.
I MEAN, COME ON,
103 YEARS OLD?
MUST BE DOING
SOMETHING RIGHT.
I LOVE THAT IT'S REAL,
AND IT'S THE WAY IT WAS.
THE WAY IT STARTED
WHEN JOHN PUCCIATTI
OPENED THE JOINT IN 1908,
AND THE WAY IT STILL IS TODAY.
MIGHT EVEN BE SOMETHING,
LIKE, OUT OF A SCORSESE MOVIE.
STARRING A COUPLE
GOOD FELLAS--
NICKY SITNYCKY
AND MIKEY ALBERT.
IT'S NICKY IN THE FRONT...
MANGIA, MANGIA,
MANGIA.
AND MIKEY IN THE BACK.
WE GOT CARBONARA
AND SAUSAGE AND PEPPERS
UP ON THE TRAY.
NICKY AND MIKEY, THEY'RE LIKE
A MARRIED COUPLE AT THIS POINT,
THEY'VE BEEN TOGETHER
FOR SO LONG.
TABLE NUMBER 4.
OKAY, GOT IT.
JUST GO OUT THE DOOR,
IT'D BE GREAT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU GUYS
HAD IT?
BEGINNING OF 1973.
WERE YOU GUYS IN THE
RESTAURANT BUSINESS AT ALL?
NEVER.
NO, WE WERE STOCKBROKERS
TOGETHER.
I SAY, "MIKEY, YOU WANT
TO BUY A RESTAURANT WITH ME?"
YOU GO--
AND I GO,
"YEAH, WHY NOT?"
THAT'S IT, EXCEPT THEY
HAD TO LEARN HOW TO RUN IT.
I SAID, "I'LL GO IN THERE,
I'LL LEARN HOW TO COOK."
SO I WENT IN THE KITCHEN,
I LEARNED.
FROM THE RESTAURANT'S
ORIGINAL COOKBOOK.
PASSED DOWN TO US FROM JOHN
TO JOHN'S SON
FROM 1908, FROM BEVAGNA,
ITALY, IN UMBRIA.
DID NOT CHANGE A THING.
ANYONE WHO'S ITALIAN
IS GOING TO RECOGNIZE
SOMETHING ON THE MENU
AND SAY, "I USED TO HAVE
THAT WHEN I WAS A KID."
VEAL MEATBALLS.
POLPETTE DI VITELLOS.
JOHN'S MAKES THE BEST
MEATBALLS I'VE HAD
SINCE MY MOTHER IN-LAW
MADE THEM.
NOT DUPLICATED ANYWHERE
OTHER THAN JOHN'S.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
POLPETTE DI VITELLO,
WHICH IS VEAL MEATBALLS.
MAKE IT RIGHT
IN THE HOUSE.
POLPETTE DI VITELLO.
DID I SAY THAT RIGHT?
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
YEAH, YOU SURE DID.
WE'RE GONNA CHOP UP
SOME VEAL.
IT'S FROZEN.
CORRECT.
GIMME BACK THE MONEY
YOU OWE ME,
YOU LOUSY PIECE OF...
PUT IT ON A TRAY.
SO BY HAVING
THE VEAL MEAT COLD,
IT'S NOT GONNA GUM UP.
EXACTLY, WE HAVE--
WHOA.
COMIN' OUT.
HEY, HEY.
FRESH VEAL,
UNADULTERATED.
I DIDN'T DULT-IFY
THIS AT ALL.
DIDN'T DULT-IFY
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA DO--
WE HAVE A LOAF OF ITALIAN BREAD.
YOU CLEAN EVERYTHING OFF
OF IT SO YOU'RE LEFT WITH
THE WHITE BREAD.
DUMP IT IN HERE, THE MILK.
INCORPORATING MOISTURE INTO IT,
BECAUSE THE VEAL'S KINDA LEAN.
EXACTLY,
HAS A BLAND TASTE.
THAT'S WHY IT PICKS EVERYTHING
UP. THIS IS AN EGG.
NOW WE GOT TWO EGGS. WE COMBINE
EVERYTHING, WE MARRY IT.
WE'RE DONE--WE'RE DONE
WITH THIS, OKAY, NOW.
OKAY, NOW WHAT?
AFTER THIS, I GET A TOWEL--
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YEAH, I'M YOUR CUT MAN.
I FEEL SPECIAL, YOU KNOW?
I'M YOUR CUT MAN.
THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
PECORINO.
SHEEP'S CHEESE.
TAKE THAT.
CHOPPED SCALLIONS.
NOW THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS
HAVE BEEN COOKING OVERNIGHT.
DUMP THAT IN, RIGHT?
NICE SUGAR THERE.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE, BASIL,
DRIED OREGANO,
SALT TO TASTE--
WE GO ONE, TWO, THREE,
AND WE'RE DONE WITH THAT.
WE DO PEPPER,
ONE--
AND A HALF.
NO TWO THREE?
NO TWO THREE.
THEN WE HAVE MINCED GARLIC.
THEN WE MIX THE WHOLE THING UP
WITH OUR HANDS.
DO YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF AN OLD NEW YORK
MOB MOVIE?
YOU'RE EITHER GONNA
LOVE THE MEATBALLS,
OR WE'RE GONNA MISS YOU.
DROP THE VEAL,
AND THEN THE MIX.
SOME MARSALA WINE,
AND MANTEQUILLA-- BUTTER.
GOING SPANISH ON ME?
SPANISH, ITALIAN, JEWISH--
DON'T MATTER, IT'S GOOD STUFF.
HIT IT.
LET'S DO IT.
YOU TAKE SOME BREADCRUMBS,
YOU GO LIKE THIS.
IT'LL WORK
INTO A NICE TIGHT MIXTURE.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE READY.
NOW WE FORM IT INTO BALLS.
GONNA BAKE THESE
ON A COOKIE SHEET.
YOU GUYS MAKE
COOKIES HERE?
IT'S NOW A MEATBALL SHEET.
ANYBODY WHO DOESN'T LIKE IT,
LET 'EM TALK TO GUY,
YOU KNOW?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THE HOMEMADE MARINARA SAUCE,
WE'RE GONNA COAT
THE COOKIE SHEET,
WHICH HAS NOW BECOME
THE MEAT SHEET.
GREAT, SO LET'S
KEEP THESE GOIN',
AND THEN WE'LL PUT 'EM
IN THE OVEN.
YOU GOT IT.
EXCELLENT.
MEATBALLS HAVE BEEN
COOLED DOWN FOR A WHILE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PREPARE THEM
FOR TABLE SERVICE.
LITTLE OLIVE OIL, BUTTER,
MARSALA WINE IN.
JUST GIVES US
THE CARAMELIZATION.
THE MEATBALLS. THIS MEATBALL'S
GIVING ME TROUBLE.
WHAT'S THE STORY, GUY?
ALL RIGHT, NOW...
HE'S TALKING TO
THE MEATBALLS.
MMM. SMELLS KILLER.
THEY READY?
THEY'RE ABSOLUTELY READY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE 'EM,
WE'RE GONNA PUT A DOLLOP
OF THE MARINARA SAUCE
ON THE PLATE.
ONE, TWO...
QUIT SHOWIN' OFF.
THREE, FOUR.
LITTLE FRESHLY CHOPPED BASIL,
IT'S GOOD TO GO.
MMM. I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING,
THAT IS ONE TENDER
MEATBALL.
INCREDIBLY FLAVORFUL,
AND THIS MARSALA--
THAT LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS
ON THE OUTSIDE--
NEVER HAVE I HAD
AN ALL-VEAL MEATBALL.
THIS IS THE WAY
TO DO IT.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL
THING.
THANK YOU.
NICE JOB. 103 YEARS OLD?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO TELL.
DOESN'T LOOK A DAY OVER 90.
THERE WE GO--THANK YOU,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT'S JUST OUTRAGEOUS.
THE WAY THEY MAKE THE MEAT
IS UNBELIEVABLE.
THEY'RE SO GOOD,
IT'S ALMOST LIKE A LITTLE SWEET,
THEN YOU TASTE THE VEAL.
BUT THE TRUE TEST
IS HOW THEY
HANDLE THE PASTA.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
FRESH HOMEMADE PASTA.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
YOU CAN DO IT,
ROCKY.
MIKEY'S MAKING IT
FROM SCRATCH.
MMM.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
AT JOHN'S ITALIAN IN
MANHATTAN'S LOWER EAST SIDE,
IT'S ALL ABOUT
TRADITION.
SAUSAGE AND PEPPERS
UP ON THE TRAY.
FROM THE CANDLES THEY'VE BEEN
BURNING SINCE 1933...
THEY WERE A CELEBRATION
OF THE END OF PROHIBITION.
AND THEY'VE ALWAYS
BEEN LIT.
TO THE REAL DEAL ITALIAN FOOD
THEY'VE BEEN CRANKING OUT
OVER A CENTURY.
RAGU ALLA JOHN'S.
OH, BEAUTIFUL.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE FRESH
HOMEMADE PASTA.
YOU WANT GREAT PAPPARDELLE,
COME HERE.
WE'LL MAKE
THE PAPPARDELLE.
PAPPARDELLE'S
NICE AND THICK,
KINDA LOOKS LIKE
A BIG FETTUCCINE.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
SEMOLINA FLOUR,
ADD SOME PEPPER, SALT,
AND BIND THIS TOGETHER.
TAKE THE EGG.
MAKE A LITTLE WELL,
INCORPORATING THAT IN.
WE'LL DO THIS ALL
BY HAND, HUH?
ALL BY HAND.
DUMP 'EM IN. THERE YOU GO.
THERE THE YOLKS.
ONE, TWO, THREE--
THE YOLKS ARE IN--
FOUR...YOU'RE A SLOW MAN, WOW.
YOU CAN DO IT, ROCKY.
YEAH, GET IT ALL OVER
THE PLACE HERE.
COME ON, KEEP SOME
IN THE BOWL, THOUGH.
THEN WE'LL KNEAD IT,
LET IT REST.
EXACTLY.
IT'S HAD A CHANCE
TO REST NOW.
CUT IT INTO ABOUT 1-INCH
STRIPS LIKE THIS.
THEN I FLOUR
THE BASE HERE.
GONNA PRESS IT DOWN.
I LIKE DOING IT FROM
THE CENTER TO THE OUTSIDE.
OKAY, SO WE START IT OFF 1--
SO 1's THE BIGGEST OPENING.
YOU WANT TO HIT
NUMBER 3 FOR ME?
AND NOW 5.
WE MEASURE IT WITH
THE LENGTH OF THE KNIFE,
SO ONE HERE,
THEN THE OTHER ONE.
SO WHAT WE DO
IS WE CUT IT BY EYEBALL.
EVERYBODY KNOWS IT'S FRESH-MADE
PASTA BECAUSE IT'S NOT EVEN.
'CAUSE IT'S NOT EVEN.
VERY NICE.
GET SOME SEMOLINA.
SO IT DOESN'T STICK TOGETHER,
PULLS OUT SOME OF THE MOISTURE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS
WITH WHAT DISH?
THE HOMEMADE TUSCAN
RAGU MEAT SAUCE.
NICE.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE.
SO CHUCK AND PORK BUTT.
CORRECT.
A COUPLE OF PIECES
AT A TIME.
CRUST BOTH SIDES.
RIGHT.
SO PUT A NICE SEAR ON
ALL THE BEEF. NOW WHAT'S UP?
WE'RE GONNA PUT OLIVE OIL
IN--EXTRA VIRGIN.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THE MEAT IN.
OKAY. YOU'VE GOT HANDS
OF STEEL, MAN.
I GUESS IT WAS
A LITTLE HOT.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY, LET THE SMOKE GO AWAY
SO WE CAN SEE EACH OTHER.
YEAH, IT'S OKAY.
'CAUSE THAT'S IMPORTANT.
ONIONS, CARROTS.
CELERY FOR THE SWEETNESS,
ALL RIGHT.
DEGLAZING FROM ALL
THE MEAT THAT WE SEARED.
EVERYTHING OFF THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAN.
2 CUPS OF MARSALA WINE.
OKAY, IN WITH THE TOMATOES.
WE'RE DONE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD IN
THE VEGETABLE STOCK.
WE MAKE IT ON THE PREMISES.
HERBS--OREGANO, BASIL.
THAT'S IT.
THEN ALL WE DO IS LOOK AT IT,
WE MAKE SURE IT'S ALL IN,
IT DIDN'T FALL
ON THE FLOOR.
YOU'RE GONNA LOOK AT IT,
YOU'RE GONNA STARE DOWN AT IT?
YEAH, YEAH,
YOU KNOW--
SAY SOMETHING TO IT?
WE'RE GONNA SAY, YOU'RE IN
THE POT, BUDDY, STAY IN THE POT.
OKAY, SO NOW THIS IS GONNA COOK
DOWN FOR HOW MUCH LONGER?
FIVE TO SEVEN HOURS.
NOW THE PASTA GOES DOWN.
OKAY, PUT IN THE FRESH-MADE
PAPPARDELLE.
WANT TO PUT THE TOP ON.
OUR CUSTOMERS LIKE THEM SOFT,
AS OPPOSED TO IMPORTED PASTA
WHEN YOU COOK IT--
YOU WANT IT AL DENTE.
98% WANT 'EM AL DENTE.
THIS--FORGET ABOUT IT,
YOU GOTTA DO IT MORE
TO THE SOFT SIDE.
TAKE THIS OFF, PAPPARDELLE
PASTA. THAT'S ALREADY DONE.
PUT IT IN THE SAUTé POT,
SO WE SAUTé IT WITH
THE TOMATO MARINARA SAUCE,
COMBINE IT, YOU MARRY IT.
GOT IT.
AND THEN WE CAN SERVE IT.
BA-DA-BING.
RIGHT ON TOP.
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF BASIL,
BASILICO,
YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
MMM.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
THAT MEAT JUST MELTS.
THAT PASTA COOKED A LITTLE BIT
MORE MAKES A DIFFERENCE.
IT'S NOT MUSHY. MMM.
AND THE MARSALA--
OLD-SCHOOL, MAKIN' IT HAPPEN,
AND STICKIN' TO THE BASICS.
I THINK HE LIKES IT.
I'M SHOVELING IT.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
HERE WE GO,
THE PAPPARDELLE,
HOMEMADE PAPPARDELLE.
THE QUALITY OF THE SAUCE,
THE FRESHNESS OF THE NOODLES,
EVERYTHING WORKING TOGETHER.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE FRESH,
HOMEMADE PASTA. PERFECT.
THIS IS BO DIETL.
I CALL HIM UNCLE BO.
THIS IS WHAT WE LIKE
ON SUNDAYS--
A LOT OF MEAT-ITATION.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
THIS JOINT EXISTED.
IT'S BEEN HERE
FOR 103 YEARS.
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU GOTTA SHOW ME
IN MY NEW YORK CITY
A GREAT JOINT LIKE THIS.
MMM.
ONE FOR GUIDO.
IT'S THE OUTSTANDING FOOD
AT THE END OF THE DAY,
WHERE YOU WANT TO GO
TO HAVE YOUR MEALS.
103 YEARS. I CAN'T BELIEVE
I MISSED IT, JUST LIKE BO DIETL,
WHERE'S THIS BEEN?
BUT I WILL PROMISE YOU,
I WILL BE BACK.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADED CROSS COUNTRY
TO SANTA BARBARA
FOR THE MAC DADDY
OF FISH AND CHIPS...
UH-HUH-MA-MA.
TOAD IN THE HOLE...
THAT'S A MEAL THERE.
AND A TRIPLE "D" FIRST...
I'M GONNA TRY HAGGIS.
MIND OVER MATTER.
SMALL MIND,
LOT OF MATTER.
SO HERE WE ARE. HUNTER AND I
ARE CRUISING STATE STREET
IN SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA,
AND WE'RE LOOKING
FOR THE REAL DEAL,
I'M TALKIN' THE AUTHENTIC
BRITISH FISH AND CHIPS JOINT,
AND I THINK THIS MIGHT BE IT.
HUNTER, GRAB US A TABLE.
DON'T START WITHOUT ME,
ALL RIGHT?
I'M ON IT.
BECAUSE THIS IS
MAC'S FISH & CHIP SHOP.
FISH CHIPS AND MUSHY PEAS
IN THE WINDOW.
FINDING A FISH AND CHIPS PLACE
IN SANTA BARBARA
IS LIKE A DREAM
COME TRUE.
BY FAR THE MOST AUTHENTIC
I'VE EVER HAD IN THE U.S.
WELL, THAT MAKES TOTAL SENSE,
SINCE OWNER
GRANT "MAC" MacNOUGHTON...
FISH IS UP.
IS A REAL-DEAL BRIT
FROM ACROSS THE POND.
ALL RIGHT, CHEF, SO I HEAR
YOU'RE THE FISH AND CHIP GUY.
IT'S TRUE, IT'S TRUE, WE MAKE
SOME GOOD FISH AND CHIPS HERE.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE
ABOUT FISH AND CHIPS?
I'M ALL ABOUT THE REAL DEAL.
I LIKE EVERYTHING--
THE CRISPINESS,
THE SALTINESS.
OKAY, MAN, WE'VE GOT SOME
KILLER FISH AND CHIPS FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT,
SO LET'S START OFF,
SO WE'RE GONNA THROW SOME
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR DOWN.
ALL RIGHT.
PAPRIKA, SOME KOSHER SALT HERE.
WE'LL GET THIS ALL
NICE AND MIXED UP.
THIS IS WHERE THE BEER COMES IN.
ALL RIGHT--
YOU WOULDN'T BELIEVE,
PARKING THE CAR--
HEY--
I'M TRYING TO PARK THE CAR,
YOU TAKE OVER MY SHOW.
THIS IS "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES" WITH GUY FIERI.
HUNTER!
CHEF, NICE TO MEET YOU.
IS MY KID BEHAVING HIMSELF
IN YOUR KITCHEN?
VERY MUCH SO.
WHERE ARE WE AT SO FAR?
YEAH, SO WE'RE MAKING
SOME, UH,
SOME OF OUR BEER BATTER
THAT GOES ON OUR CRISPY FISH.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME BEER IN.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR THE FIZZIER
THE BEER, THE BETTER.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE LOOKING
TO GET THIS NICE AND STICKY
TO START OFF WITH, SO NOW WE
KINDA GOT THIS KINDA PASTE.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE A BREAD DOUGH.
SOME COLD WATER.
SO THIS BATTER'S
PRETTY MUCH READY NOW.
LET'S START ROCKIN'
AND ROLLIN'.
NEXT STEP, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR DRY DREDGE.
ALL RIGHT,
NOW SEASONED FLOUR.
KOSHER SALT IN THERE.
AND A LITTLE PEPPER.
READY TO GO.
NOW THE STAR OF THE SHOW.
WE USE WILD ALASKAN COD.
SUPER SUSTAINABLE.
HOW MANY PIECES DO YOU GET
WITH AN ORDER?
ONE WHOLE FILLET,
SO WE'RE LOOKING AT AROUND
AN 8-OUNCE PIECE OF FISH.
NICE.
WE'RE GONNA DROP IT
INTO THE SEASONED FLOUR,
MAKE SURE IT GETS
COMPLETELY COVERED,
DROP IT INTO THE BATTER,
POP IT IN, LET IT FLOAT AWAY.
HOW LONG DOES THIS TAKE?
THREE OR FOUR MINUTES.
THESE FISH ARE PRETTY CLOSE
TO BEING READY,
WE DEFINITELY WANT TO GET
THESE CHIPS DROPPED NOW.
SO YOU DON'T CALL 'EM FRIES,
YOU CALL 'EM--
WE CALL 'EM CHIPS, YEAH.
THEY'RE A MUCH
THICKER CUT.
ALL RIGHT, SO THESE FRIES
ARE READY NOW.
OH, I'M CALLING 'EM FRIES.
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
YOU'RE AMERICANIZING ME.
GO AHEAD AND PULL
THOSE FRIES OUT.
ALL RIGHT, THESE CHIPS
ARE DONE.
OUR FISH ARE THERE RESTING
READY FOR US AS WELL,
AND LET'S GET THIS
PLATED UP. DIG IN.
FRESH FISH, HAND BATTERED.
CHIPS YOU MAKE YOURSELF.
LOOK HOW THIN THAT BATTER IS.
YEAH, I LIKE THAT
A LOT BETTER,
'CAUSE YOU GO TO
A FISH AND CHIP PLACE,
AND THE BATTER WILL BE LIKE
2 INCHES THICK.
I WENT TO, UH, LONDON
WHEN I WAS A KID,
WHEN I WAS AN EXCHANGE
STUDENT IN FRANCE,
HAD SOME FISH AND CHIPS--THE
WHOLE EXPERIENCE IS COMIN' BACK.
MY FRIEND, THAT'S
THE REAL DEAL.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
THANK YOU, MAN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
AWESOME JOB.
AWESOME.
(woman) FISH, CHIPS,
AND COLE SLAW.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT
THE FISH AND CHIPS HERE
THAT MAKE 'EM SO GOOD?
IT'S JUST THAT FRESH
SORT OF CRISPINESS,
BUT YOU STILL GET
THE LIGHTNESS OF THE FISH.
A NICE PIECE OF COD,
NICE AND TENDER.
IT'S THE FIRST MEAL THAT I HAD
WHEN I WALKED INTO MAC'S.
THIS IS AS AUTHENTIC
AS IT GETS HERE.
THERE ISN'T ANYTHING ELSE
LIKE THAT AROUND.
EXACTLY WHAT MAC
AND HIS WIFE KATE THOUGHT
AFTER LANDING IN SANTA BARBARA.
WE WENT ON A ROAD TRIP.
WE WERE AWAY FOR SEVEN MONTHS.
THIS WAS PRETTY MUCH THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL PLACE WE FOUND.
WE THOUGHT, THERE'S NO GOOD
FISH AND CHIPS HERE--
LET'S OPEN ONE.
(man) ♪ I DON'T CARE,
AND YOU DON'T MATTER ♪
THE MENU IS 100%
AUTHENTIC BRITISH.
MY FAVORITE THING ON THE MENU
IS THE TOAD IN THE HOLE.
(woman) IT'S YORKSHIRE PUDDING
WITH MASHED POTATOES
AND GRAVY, AND THEN FRIED
SAUSAGE ON TOP. IT'S FANTASTIC.
AND IT STARTS OFF WITH A RECIPE
THAT'S ALWAYS BEEN
KINDA MY CULINARY
KILIMANJARO--
THE REAL DEAL
YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S GET
OUR EGGS DOWN.
LET'S GIVE 'EM A LITTLE WHISK,
BREAK THOSE YOLKS UP.
STIR IT UP, LET'S PUT
SOME FLOUR IN THERE,
LET'S GET SOME
MILK IN THERE.
SO IT IS EQUAL PARTS?
YEAH, IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE EQUAL PARTS,
BY MEASUREMENT,
NOT BY WEIGHT.
I LIKE TO TRY AND JUST DO
THE MILK BY EYE THOUGH.
THAT HELPED ME.
I CAN'T MAKE IT
IN THE FIRST PLACE,
AND NOW YOU'RE GONNA SAY,
"EQUAL PARTS, AND THEN NOT."
IF YOU NEED THE RECIPE,
YOU CAN WATCH THE SHOW.
IT WILL BE ON THERE.
GOOD NIGHT!
PROBLEM WITH THIS RIGHT NOW--
HAVE SOME BUBBLES IN THERE,
AND WE NEED TO LET THOSE
SETTLE OFF,
SO I'M GONNA SHOVE IT
DOWN INTO A PITCHER,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA LEAVE IT
TO REST FOR ABOUT HALF AN HOUR.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM
WITH THE BUBBLES?
THOSE BUBBLES IN THERE,
IF IT'S NOT BEEN ALLOWED
TO SETTLE,
THEN THEY DON'T RISE
AS WELL IN THE OVEN.
SO NOW WE'VE GOT
THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING PANS,
HAVE PREHEATED IN THERE.
SO WHEN YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA BE
SERVING YORKSHIRE PUDDING,
YOU HAVE 'EM IN THERE
READY TO GO.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO YOU GOTTA GET
THE PAN HOT.
YOU WANT TO GET SOME OIL IN
THERE, GET THAT OIL SMOKING HOT.
BACK IN FOR 15 MINUTES,
THEN WE HIT THE BATTER TO IT?
EXACTLY. GET IT DONE.
AND--GO!
SOMEONE COULD GET
BURNED DOING THIS.
NICE. OKAY, HOW LONG'S
THIS GONNA COOK OFF?
WE NEED THESE, LIKE,
20 MINUTES,
AND WE DON'T WANT
TO OPEN THAT DOOR.
THEY'RE JUST GONNA DEFLATE.
WHY DID HE SAY IT
THAT WAY?
'CAUSE YOU KNOW
I WANT TO LOOK.
OKAY, IS IT READY?
YEAH, I THINK
WE SHOULD BE GOOD.
OH!
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE WITH THIS?
BANGERS AND MASH
WITH GRAVY.
YOU CALL THIS A BANGER?
THE NAME COMES FROM, UH,
DURING THE WORLD WAR, THEY WOULD
LITERALLY POP ON THE FIRE.
THESE ARE MADE BY A LOCAL
BUTCHER TO OUR RECIPE.
HOW WILL IT GET
FINISHED?
SO IT'S GONNA GET
FINISHED IN THE FRYER.
THAT'S GONNA GIVE IT
A LITTLE CRISPINESS
AND A LITTLE COLOR
ON THE OUTSIDE.
AND THE GRAVY--
MIREPOIX, DRIPPINGS
FROM THE SAUSAGE?
YEAH, NO, NONE OF THAT.
UM, SO WE--
NONE OF THAT?
WE'RE NOT LOOKING TO MAKE
THAT KIND OF GRAVY.
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR
IS A FISH AND CHIP SHOP GRAVY,
AND THE BEST WAY WE'VE BEEN
ABLE TO REPLICATE THAT,
WITH NO SHAME,
IS A POWDERED GRAVY.
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
YES!
START PLATING.
THAT ONE'S YOURS.
SO WE GET A WHOLE BUNCH
OF OUR MASHED POTATO.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE TWO SAUSAGES,
CROSS 'EM ON TOP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA FINISH
THIS OFF--GOURMET GRAVY.
THAT'S A MEAL THERE.
AWESOME, MAN.
THIS IS LIKE
A THANKSGIVING MEAL.
THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING
IS SO LIGHT AND FLUFFY,
AND JUST AMAZING
HOW IT WORKS OUT.
SAUSAGE IS NICE,
NICE FLAVOR TO IT.
NICE TEXTURE IN THERE. MMM.
THAT'S GOOD FAKE GRAVY.
THANK YOU, MAN.
YOU'RE THE MAC.
(woman) THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING
IS REALLY NICE AND FLAKY.
(man) THERE'S SOME NICE
PEPPERY SPICINESS IN THERE.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
DEFINITELY COMFORT FOOD.
SO WE'VE DONE IT, MAN.
WE'VE HAD THE FISH AND CHIPS.
WE'VE HAD
THE TOAD IN THE HOLE.
THERE'S ONE THING THAT
I'M REALLY KINDA ON THE FENCE
ABOUT TRYING,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
IT'S ON THE MENU.
HAGGIS.
(laughs)
WE'LL SEE WHEN
WE GET BACK.
I'M SCARED.
I CAN DO THIS,
I CAN DO THIS.
WELCOME BACK. WE'RE HERE
AT MAC'S FISH SHOP
IN SANTA BARBARA,
CALIFORNIA,
AND IT IS THAT TIME
THAT I HAVE BEEN AVOIDING
FOR THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS,
AND THAT WAS THAT WE WERE
GONNA STUMBLE UPON A PLACE
THAT MADE...
HAGGIS!
I'M GONNA TRY HAGGIS.
WHAT IS HAGGIS?
SO HAGGIS IS THE STUFF
THEY NORMALLY THROW AWAY.
MMM, HEART...
YEAH!
TONGUE...
MY ALL-TIME FAVORITE--
YUM-O LIVER.
YEAH. OKAY, AND THEN SUET,
AND THEN THE BEEF FAT.
AND IT'S ALL BOILED UP
INSIDE A STOMACH.
INSIDE A SHEEP STOMACH.
TRADITIONALLY, THAT'S HOW
IT WOULD BE DONE, YEAH.
WE'RE NOT GONNA DO IT
TRADITIONALLY THAT WAY
BECAUSE WE'RE NOT GONNA HAVE
THE SHEEP STOMACH,
AND WE'RE NOT GONNA HAVE
THE LUNG BECAUSE...
WE'RE NOT ALLOWED TO
IN THE U.S.
WE'RE JUST SO TIGHT
ON THOSE RULES, AREN'T WE?
WHY DO YOU PUT THIS
ON THE MENU?
MY DAD'S SIDE OF THE FAMILY
ARE ALL SCOTTISH,
SO IT'S A VERY TRADITIONAL
SCOTTISH DISH.
LET'S GO, SO LIVER,
HEART, TONGUE.
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL CHOPPED UP NEATLY.
THE HEART AND THE TONGUE
ARE GONNA GET BOILED AWAY
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES,
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT THE LIVER
IN FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND ADD SOME FLAVOR TO THIS?
YEAH, WE'RE GONNA
PUT ONIONS IN.
YOU COULDN'T PUT
ENOUGH ONIONS IN.
SO NOW THAT THIS IS ALL
COOKED THROUGH,
WE WANT TO STRAIN
IT ALL OFF.
A LITTLE OF THE BEEF SUET,
A LITTLE OF THE BEEF FAT.
YEAH.
AND A LITTLE LAYERED EFFECT,
A BIT OF AN ORGAN LASAGNA
ON THE GO.
WHEW.
PUNGENT.
YEAH. NOW?
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
RESERVE SOME OF THE STOCK,
AND THEN WE CAN USE THAT
TO MOISTEN IT UP LATER.
AND THAT'S READY
FOR GRINDING.
I CAN DO THIS,
I CAN DO THIS.
MIND OVER MATTER.
SMALL MIND,
LOT OF MATTER.
LET'S GRIND IT UP.
AND THERE SHE BLOWS.
NO, THAT'LL BE ME.
THE NEXT STEP
IS WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS UP
WITH ALL OUR DRY INGREDIENTS.
WE'VE GOT SOME OATS
THAT GET ROASTED,
AND WE HAVE A WHOLE BUNCH
OF HERBS AND SPICES--
ROSEMARY, WE'RE GONNA ADD
A BUNCH OF THYME INTO IT,
TARRAGON, PAPRIKA,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
A LITTLE CUMIN GOING DOWN,
SALT AND GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
GONNA GIVE IT A GOOD MIX UP,
AND THEN WE ADD IN
THE GROUND ORGAN MEAT.
SO NOW WE COVER IT WITH
THE ALUMINUM FOIL
AND BAKE IT OFF AT 350
FOR 2 HOURS.
READY TO ROCK.
ALL RIGHT, SO THIS
CAME OUT THE OVEN.
UNVEILED. WE'RE GONNA
TAKE A GOOD PORTION,
WE'RE GONNA CREATE
A NICE LITTLE, UH--
DON'T--YOU KNOW,
I HAD A BIG--
I HAD A BIG LUNCH.
GOES INTO THE SEASON
DREDGING FLOUR,
GONNA COME ACROSS INTO
OUR BATTER, GIVE IT A SPIN.
JUST GET THE BATTER
NICE AND CRISPY.
THERE IS NO WAY YOU COULD
EVER FRY THAT LONG ENOUGH.
WE'RE THERE NOW. GIVE YOU
THE STRAIGHT-UP VERSION.
HERE WE ARE.
I'LL DO THE TALKING BIT--
MMM, THAT WAS
DELICIOUS.
THAT WAS MONEY.
I MEAN, TO BE VERY HONEST
ABOUT IT,
THIS IS BROKEN DOWN
SO THERE'S ALMOST
NO RECOGNIZING ANY
OF THE ORGAN MEAT TEXTURE.
THERE IS GOOD
SEASONING TO IT.
IS IT AS CRAZY AND SCARY
AS I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA BE?
NO. UM, WILL IT BE FUN
TO HAVE HUNTER TRY IT?
YES. HUNTER!
WHAT'S UP, DAD?
IT'S A SCOTTISH
McNUGGET.
HE'S LOOKING
FOR A VENTRICLE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
AWESOME?
GREAT.
WOW.
HAGGIS AND CHIPS
IN THE WINDOW.
THIS IS JUST LIKE PERFECT
THROUGH AND THROUGH.
RICH, ALMOST BUTTERY
FLAVOR TO IT.
SORT OF GOT THIS SPICY
SAVORY FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S NICE. I'M A FAN.
I'M CONVERTED.
IF YOU WERE HAVING IT
IN EDINBURGH,
YOU'D BE GETTING THE SAME
EXACT FLAVOR--
MAYBE NOT AS GOOD AS MAC'S.
NOT ONLY IS IT, YOU KNOW,
AUTHENTIC,
IT'S UP THERE WITH THE BEST
FISH AND CHIP PLACES
THAT YOU WOULD GET IN THE U.K.
THERE'S SOME THINGS
WE'RE JUST GOOD AT--
CLASSIC FOOD, COMFORT FOOD,
AND WE DO IT WELL.
AND HERE, YOU DO IT
AUTHENTIC.
UH-HUH.
REAL DEAL.
ACCENT AND ALL.
INDEED.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
I'VE NEVER REALLY
RECOGNIZED
HOW MUCH I NEED
CRUNCHY BATTER,
BUT I MIGHT NAME ONE OF MY
NEXT KIDS CRUNCHY BATTER.
COME HERE,
LITTLE CRUNCHY BATTER.
(laughs)