HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ARE YOU GUYS READY FOR THIS?
WATCH.
WE'RE HEADIN'
FROM COAST TO COAST...
YOU LOOK LIKE
A GET-AT-IT GUY.
IN TAMPA BAY...
A LITTLE BIT
ON THE JUICY SIDE.
THIS SIDEWALK STAND...
SHAKIN' IT HERE BOSS.
DID I JUST GET
A LITTLE "COOL HAND LUKE?"
THANK YOU.
SERVIN' UP AN ALL-STAR MIX...
WHOO, WHOO.
OF BURGERS...
GOT A NOLAN RYAN
GOING OUT FRONT.
AND BASEBALL...
TRIPLE PLAY, THREE MEATS,
TRIPLE "D," YOU SEE ME
HUN-GR-Y.
OUT OF THE PARK, BABY.
EH, HA.
AND IN VANCOUVER, B.C...
THAT'S WHAT I'M LOOKIN' FOR.
QUICKLY. THEY'RE PUFFING DOWN.
THE OLDEST FAMILY-RUN JOINT
IN TOWN...
THIS PLACE
IS AN INSTITUTION.
CARVIN' OUT THE CLASSICS...
YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
FOR DECADES...
THAT SHOULD BE BUTTER.
NO, THIS IS A 100-YEAR-OLD
RECIPE.
OKAY, THEN.
THIS IS A BOAT
GOING TO FLAVOR TOWN.
(imitating chugging)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
ON TRIPLE "D,"
WE LOVE VISITING THE JOINTS
THAT ARE PART OF HISTORY.
WE'RE HERE IN NORTH VANCOUVER,
BRITISH COLUMBIA,
ABOUT OVER THE LIONS GATE BRIDGE
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT IS THE OLDEST FAMILY-RUN
RESTAURANT IN VANCOUVER.
THIS IS THE TOMAHAWK.
STEAK AND MUSHROOM PIE.
THIS PLACE
IS AN INSTITUTION.
YEAH.
BEEF DIP.
IT'S WHERE I GREW UP.
IT'S JUST
BECOME AN ICON.
YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
AND SO IS SECOND-GENERATION
OWNER CHUCK CHAMBERLAIN...
CHUCK IS THE TOMAHAWK, PERIOD.
WHO TOOK OVER THE JOINT
AFTER HIS PARENTS OPENED IT
BACK IN 1926.
(Chuck) WHEN MOM AND DAD
STARTED,
THEY HAD NO IDEA
ON HOW TO COOK,
BUT THE RESTAURANT WAS MORE
OF A MEETING PLACE AT THAT TIME.
BUT TODAY,
FOLKS COME FOR THE FOOD...
MIXED GRILL UP.
AND THAT'S ALL THANKS
TO HEAD CHEF ANNE ZUBAIDI...
STEAK AND MUSHROOM PIE UP.
WHO COOKED IN RESTAURANTS
AROUND THE WORLD
BEFORE MOVING TO CANADA.
BECAUSE I WANTED
TO LEARN CANADIAN COOKING.
EH.
THAT'S WHAT YOU SAY,
RIGHT, EH?
EH.
(laughs)
AND SHE BROUGHT
AN ENGLISH FAVORITE
THAT PEOPLE HERE
GO BANANAS FOR.
AND YOU KNOW,
BANANAS IS GOOD...
YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
SERVED ALONGSIDE
THEIR ROAST BEEF DINNER.
WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE THING
ON THE MENU?
BESIDE THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING?
OH.
I KNOW IT'S GONNA BE GOOD
EVERY TIME.
I'VE BEEN WAITING TO MAKE
YORKSHIRE PUDDING FOR YEARS.
AS MY CAREER WENT ON
BEING A CHEF,
I HAD
TO MAKE YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
I SUCK
AT MAKING YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
IT JUST ALWAYS HAS BEEN, LIKE,
REALLY FLAT BREAD MUFFINS...
(laughs)
THAT DON'T TASTE GOOD
AT ALL.
I AM NOW YOUR DISCIPLE.
SO WE HAVE FLOUR.
WE'VE GOT FOUR EGGS.
AND WE GIVE THEM
A LITTLE WHISK.
AND THEN WE'RE ADDING MILK
AND PLAIN WATER.
WE'VE GOT THAT MIXED.
A PINCH OF SALT TO THE FLOUR.
WE START THAT WHISKING. THEN WE
POUR THE LIQUID IN SLOWLY...
IS THIS WHEN
THE MAGIC HAPPENS?
THIS IS WHEN
MAGIC HAPPENS.
IT MIXES
UNTIL IT'S NOT LUMPY.
OKAY, THAT'S DONE.
AND SO WE HAVE OUR PAN.
THIS IS ABOUT 50 YEARS OLD.
WELL, IT'S GONNA BE LEAVIN'
IN A RED CAMARO.
(laughs)
IF THIS IS A MAGIC MUFFIN TIN,
I'M TAKIN' IT.
WE'RE PUTTING
BEEF DRIPPINGS IN,
BECAUSE THEY ARE
WHAT MAKE IT BEAUTIFUL.
THIS GOES INTO THE OVEN.
I'VE COME TO UNDERSTAND
A CERTAIN LEVEL OF DEPRESSION
WHEN I'VE TRIED
TO DO THESE,
AND THEY'VE NOT COME OUT
PUFFY McMAGIC.
YES.
THEY'VE COME OUT FLAT
McTRAGIC.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS.
I'M JUST GONNA LEAVE
ON THAT ONE.
SO WE'VE GOT THE YORKSHIRE
PUDDING PAN READY,
AND IT'S GOING
TO SIZZLE.
SPOT-CHECKING YOU
RIGHT HERE.
THERE YOU GO. LOOKIN' GOOD.
SOME IN THE BACK.
OH, CAN'T MISS THOSE ONES.
THEN THEY GO
BACK IN THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP ARE WE AT?
400.
AND THEY WILL
BE PUFFY McMAGIC.
IN ABOUT HALF AN HOUR.
OH, I CAN'T WAIT
THAT LONG.
YOU HAVE TO WAIT
FOR SOMETHING GOOD.
LOOK.
SEE IF THEY'RE READY.
NO PEEKING.
SET YOUR WATCH, MR. BLING.
OKAY, NEXT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
THE ROAST BEEF TOP SIRLOIN.
SO I MAKE A LITTLE SCORING
ON THE TOP.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT GRAINY MUSTARD,
MONTREAL STEAK SPICE.
THEN WE JUST
MASSAGE IT IN.
ROAST OFF IN THE OVEN
AT WHAT TEMP?
350,
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
WE'VE GOT
THE BEEF DRIPPINGS.
WE'RE GONNA SCRAPE
ALL THIS GOODNESS FROM THE PAN
INTO MY STOCKPOT.
AND WE'RE BRINGING THAT
UP TO A NICE SIZZLE,
ADDING FLOUR.
SO WE'RE MAKING GRAVY.
WE'RE MAKING GRAVY.
AND WHERE DID THE AU JUS
COME FROM?
WE MAKE OUR OWN BEEF STOCK.
WE BROWN THE BONES.
WE DO.
OF COURSE,
WE BROWN THE BONES,
AND WE MAKE
THE--FROM STOCK--OH.
LOOK HOW DARK AND RICH
AND BEAUTIFUL THAT IS.
PUT THAT IN THE BACK
OF THE CAMARO, TOO.
IT'S DOING ITS THICKENING,
AND IT'S DONE.
OKAY.
HERE, YORKSHIRE PUDDINGS.
OKAY, HERE WE GO.
ARE YOU GUYS READY FOR THIS?
WATCH.
HA.
HERE WE GO.
THAT'S WHAT
I'M LOOKIN' FOR.
ABSOLUTELY NOT
HOW MINE LOOK.
QUICKLY.
THEY'RE PUFFING DOWN.
NOW DO WE START
SLICING MEAT?
WOULD YOU LIKE
THE BIG ONE?
OKAY.
BEAUTIFUL GRAVY
OVER EVERYTHING.
TWO KNIVES AND FORKS.
(laughs)
GO AHEAD.
OH, MMM.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
I HAVEN'T HAD THAT PUFFY TYPE
OF YORKSHIRE PUDDING
IN 20-SOME YEARS.
IT'S ALL IN
THE HOMEMADE MASHED POTATOES
WITH THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING,
A LITTLE
OF THE WHOLE-GRAIN MUSTARD,
AND THEN YOU GET THAT REALLY
TENDER PUFF FROM THE PASTRY.
MMM. IT'S REALLY--
MORE GRAVY, PLEASE.
FOR YOU, ANYTHING.
OH, THAT IS GOOD STUFF.
FANTASTIC JOB.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S WHAT
I WAS LOOKING FOR.
ROAST BEEF DINNER.
THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING--
I WON'T TRY ANYBODY ELSE'S.
IT'S PERFECT.
(man) ROAST BEEF DINNER--
IT'S VERY TENDER.
HONESTLY,
IT REMINDS ME OF MOM'S.
YOU KNOW THE ONLY THING WRONG
WITH YORKSHIRE PUDDING?
TELL ME.
IT EVENTUALLY RUNS OUT.
PLUS, THEY'VE GOTTA
SAVE SOME OF THAT BEEF
FOR THEIR BIGGEST SELLER.
BEEF DIP.
I AM HAVING THE BEEF DIP.
IT IS VERY GOOD.
BUT IF YOU'RE
FROM THE LOWER 48,
YOU MIGHT KNOW IT AS FRENCH DIP
OR A TRI-TIP SANDWICH.
NOW WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
MORE BEEF. WE'RE GONNA DO
THE BEEF DIP SANDWICH,
I'M GONNA TAKE THE ENGINE
RIGHT OUT OF THE CAMARO,
JUST SO YOU KNOW,
AND START PEDDLING
THAT THING LIKE BAMM-BAMM.
WE HAVE THE PAN JUICES.
WE'VE GOT BEEF STOCK.
SO WE'RE GONNA
DEGLAZE THE PAN.
AND NOT TIGHTEN IT UP
WITH ANY FLOUR, ANY ROUX.
NOTHING.
OKAY, WE HAVE
THE AU JUS.
WE'VE GOT OUR
THINLY SLICED ROAST.
MEDIUM RARE.
AND IT GOES
INTO THE POT.
NOW ANOTHER GUILTY PLEASURE
I NEED TO LET YOU KNOW ABOUT
IS I AM
A FRENCH DIP FREAK.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ASSEMBLE.
WE HAVE OUR TOASTED BREAD,
GARLIC BUTTER, SWISS CHEESE,
AND THEN THE STUFF
THAT YOU REALLY DON'T LIKE--
NICE AND JUICY.
ARE YOU GOING SLOW
JUST TO TORTURE ME?
YES, OF COURSE.
AND THEN WE
PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
WE'RE GONNA SLICE IT IN HALF
FOR YOU.
GIVE YOU
THE GOOD STUFF HERE.
NINE LADLES
TO FILL THE LITTLE CUP.
SEE WHERE THE MEAT
IS STARTING TO GET TOGETHER?
THEY'RE HAVING, LIKE,
A LITTLE PARTY RIGHT HERE?
CHEESE IS STILL NOT FEELING
PART OF THE PARTY
TILL YOU WARM 'EM UP.
THERE'S SO MANY THINGS
THAT MAKE THIS SO RIGHT.
THE BREAD--
PERFECT, GREAT CRUNCH,
THE GARLIC BUTTER--
OH, PRIME TIME.
WHAT I THINK
THE REAL KICKER IS,
THE MEAT WAS ROASTED WITH
THAT WHOLE-GRAIN MUSTARD,
BUT YOU REALLY TASTE THE MEAT--
WHAT'S THAT OVER THERE?
I GUESS
I'LL WIPE MY FACE.
BEEF DIP.
THE MEAT IS EXTREMELY TENDER,
AND THE GRAVY IS DELICIOUS.
BEEF DIP.
(woman) THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC IN IT,
WHICH GIVES IT A NICE FLAVOR.
IT'S MY CLASSIC AT A RESTAURANT.
(Guy) I THINK THAT
PRETTY MUCH SUMS IT UP.
WE'VE HAD YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
WE'VE HAD PHENOMENAL BEEF DIP.
AND, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WHEN WE COME BACK,
HANGING OUT AT THE TOMAHAWK,
VANCOUVER, BRITISH COLUMBIA,
THERE WILL BE MORE,
AND IT WILL INVOLVE...
STEAK AND MUSHROOM PIE.
I'M A DEAD MAN.
ALL RIGHT, TRIPLE "D" HERE
IN NORTH VANCOUVER,
AND I AM SIR BEEFS-A-LOT.
WE ARE HANGING OUT
AT THE TOMAHAWK.
THIS KIND YOUNG LADY HERE
HAS BEEN FEEDING ME BEEF
SIX WAYS TO SUNDAY.
WE HAVE HAD
THE YORKSHIRE PUDDING.
YES.
WE'VE HAD THE BEEF DIP
WITH BEEF AU JUS.
AND NOW GUESS WHAT
WE'RE GONNA HAVE, HMM?
STEAK AND MUSHROOM PIE
WITH GRAVY.
ABSOLUTELY WE ARE.
AND I'M GONNA PUSH THE CAR
BACK OVER THE BIG BRIDGE
THAT I GOT HERE ON.
HOW DO WE START THIS?
THE PIE DOUGH
FOR THE POTPIE SHELL.
START IT OFF.
THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR
GOES INTO OUR BIG MIXER,
SALT AND BAKING POWDER,
SHORTENING--ALL VEGETABLE.
NOTHING SHORT ABOUT THAT.
WE PUT ON THE MACHINE.
NOW, UH, I DON'T WANT
TO GET A CALL FROM PAULA DEEN.
THAT SHOULD BE BUTTER.
YEAH, NO,
THIS IS A 100-YEAR-OLD RECIPE.
NO.
OKAY, THEN.
PAULA, HANDS OFF.
THIS IS A 100-YEAR-OLD RECIPE.
NOT MY GIG.
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX IT.
THAT'S, LIKE,
AN EXTRA 14 HOURS AT THE GYM.
WE'RE GONNA SPEED IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
MAKING SOME GRAVEL.
WE'RE MAKING GRAVEL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND YOU SAID THIS RECIPE
IS HOW OLD?
OVER 100 YEARS.
CHUCK IS THE OWNER,
AND HIS MOM AND DAD
STARTED THE TOMAHAWK
IN 1926.
NOW WE ADD WATER.
AND WE BRING IT TOGETHER,
AND THERE, IT'S DONE.
OKAY.
IT COMES OUT OF THE BOWL
TO REST FOR AN HOUR.
WE ROLL IT OUT,
FORM IT.
ROLL IT OUT.
WE BLIND-BAKE IT
WITH AN EGG WASH
SO THEY'RE NICE AND GOLDEN.
THEN WE BLIND-BAKE THE LIDS
SEPARATELY.
THIS A BOAT GOING TO FLAVOR TOWN
RIGHT THERE.
(imitates chugging)
THEN WE MAKE THE STEAK
AND MUSHROOM PIE FILLING.
WE'VE GOT THE BUTTER MELTING
WITH THE GARLIC IN IT.
WE'VE GOT
THE NICE HAPPY STEAK.
WE'RE GOING TO PUT THE STEAK
INTO THE GARLIC BUTTER.
A LITTLE
CRACKED BL--BLACK PEPPER.
IT'S EASY
FOR YOU TO SAY.
YEAH, NOT REALLY.
A LITTLE SALT.
ALL THAT'S
GONNA GO IN THERE?
MORE OR LESS.
WELL, IT'S EITHER MORE,
OR IT'S LESS.
DEFINITELY MORE, BECAUSE IT'S
GONNA FLOW OVER THE SIDE.
MUSHROOMS.
AND OF COURSE, YOU'RE GONNA
TAKE US TO GRAVY TOWN.
GRAVY TOWN.
OH, SEE,
THIS IS AWESOME.
SO WE COAT ALL THE STEAK,
ALL THE MUSHROOMS.
ALL THE FLAVORS
ARE COMING TOGETHER.
I FEEL LIKE I'M IN, LIKE,
PRAYER MEDITATION
THE WAY YOU'RE SAYING, "ALL
THE STEAK, ALL THE MUSHROOMS...
THAT'S WHAT
IT FEELS LIKE, RIGHT?
ALL THE GRAVY'S
COMING TOGETHER."
SOMEBODY PLAY THE DIDGERIDOO
RIGHT NOW.
WAH WAH WAH
WAH WAH WAH.
(laughs)
OKAY, AND THEN THIS
IS READY TO SERVE.
WE LIKE
TO STACK IT HIGH.
AND THEN TO PLATE IT,
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S HOW
IT COMES OUT.
IT LOOKS TOO PRETTY
TO BREAK INTO.
MMM.
THAT FLAKY CRUST
IS JUST SOAKING UP THE GRAVY.
HERE'S WHAT MAKES IT--
THE MUSHROOMS,
THE SCRATCH-MADE GRAVY,
THE COPIOUS AMOUNTS
OF SHORTENING,
ALL PUT TOGETHER,
AND THE TENDER BEEF.
IT'S COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S A 100-YEAR-OLD RECIPE.
EXCELLENT JOB.
THANK YOU.
YOU ROCKED IT.
YOU ARE THE BEEF-A-NATOR.
(laughs)
STEAK AND MUSHROOM PIE UP.
(woman) LOTS OF STEAK,
LOTS OF MUSHROOMS,
THE RICH GRAVY--
IT'S VERY GOOD.
IT'S LIKE A PIECE OF BREAD
THAT COMES ON TOP.
IT WORKS PERFECTLY AS YOU
CRUMBLE IT INTO THE MEAT ITSELF.
IT'S EXACTLY THE TOMAHAWK TASTE
THAT I LOVE,
WHICH IS THE HOME COOKING.
WE LOVE TO HAVE
OUR COMMUNITY RESTAURANTS,
BUT ONE THAT'S
BEEN AROUND THIS LONG,
TO BE THE LONGEST FAMILY-RUN
RESTAURANT IN VANCOUVER...
(Chuck) RIGHT.
SINCE 1926?
1926, RIGHT, YEAH.
AMAZING. CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANKS FOR HAVING US.
THANKS, GUY.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
UP NEXT...
CUT ME, MICK.
WE'RE HEADED TO TAMPA...
I LIKE TO EAT,
AND I'M A SPORTS GUY.
WHERE SOME
ALL-STAR SANDWICHES...
GOT A NOLAN RYAN.
ARE HITTIN' THE GRILL.
WHOO, WHOO.
EVERYBODY'S AT THE PARTY, MAN.
WHEN YOU'RE CRUISIN' DOWN
FALKENBURG ROAD
ABOUT 10 MILES OUTSIDE OF TAMPA,
DO WHAT I ALWAYS ASK YOU TO DO.
SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
OTHERWISE, YOU MIGHT BLOW
RIGHT BY A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT
AND NEIGHBORHOOD FAVORITE
KNOWN AS DANNY'S ALL-AMERICAN
DINER & DAIRY BAR.
CHILI CHEESE BURGER.
OH, MY GOD.
I LOVE THE BURGERS.
CHILI DOG.
(man) IT'S A MONSTER.
LOVE IT.
THERE ARE A LOT
OF HAMBURGER JOINTS
BUT NOT QUITE LIKE THIS ONE.
IT'S AMAZING. REALLY GOOD
HOME-COOKED TASTE TO IT.
BECAUSE OWNER DANNY DOAK
GREW UP COOKING AT HOME
WITH HIS MOM.
I WAS AROUND THE KITCHEN
AS A YOUNGSTER WITH MY MOM.
SHE WAS
A REAL GOOD COOK.
I GOT A MOJO COMING UP.
AND AFTER COOKING
ALL OVER THE STATES...
I'VE COOKED IN ALASKA,
NEW HAMPSHIRE, NORTH CAROLINA,
EVEN IN THE MARINES.
DANNY AND HIS WIFE GAIL
BOUGHT THIS JOINT...
(Gail) I GOT FRIES WITH
BOTH OF THOSE BURGERS.
AND COMBINED
TWO LIFELONG HOBBIES...
I LIKE TO EAT,
AND I'M A SPORTS GUY.
WE TRY TO MAKE EVERYTHING
BASEBALL REFERENCES HERE.
STARTING WITH THEIR
BEST-SELLING BURGERS.
BACON BURGER UP.
LET'S ROLL WITH IT, PLEASE.
NAMED AFTER HALL-OF-FAMERS
FROM THE NOLAN RYAN...
GOT A NOLAN RYAN GOING
OUT FRONT. LET'S GO WITH IT.
LOADED WITH CHEDDAR,
HAM, BACON,
AND BARBECUE SAUCE,
TO THE ROBERTO CLEMENTE
WITH SAUTéED ONIONS
AND SWISS CHEESE
ON CUBAN BREAD...
I CAN NEVER GET ENOUGH OF IT.
OR HIS HOME RUN
CHILI CHEESEBURGER...
I GOT A HOME RUN
CHILI CHEESEBURGER UP.
TOPPED WITH HIS WIFE'S
SCRATCH-MADE CHILI.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
THE CHILI CHEESE.
DELICIOUS.
IT'S AMAZING,
BECAUSE THE CHILI'S SO GOOD.
SO YOU MAKE
YOUR OWN CHILI.
I MAKE
MY OWN CHILI.
I'VE HAD A FEW CHILI DOGS,
CHILI BURGERS, CHILIES,
IN MY LIFE,
AND I KNOW, I KNOW,
IT'S NOT WHAT YOU'RE
EXPECTING TO HEAR FROM ME,
BECAUSE I LOOK LIKE
I EAT SALAD A LOT.
(laughs)
HERE WE GO.
WE'LL START OUT
WITH SOME OLIVE OIL,
DICED PEPPERS,
SPANISH SWEET RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE GONNA STIR THAT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
THOSE HAVE HAD A CHANCE
TO SWEAT DOWN.
THEN I'M GONNA
ADD THE BURGERS.
THE BURGER MEAT
THAT'S MADE,
YOU NOW BREAK THAT UP
AND DROP THAT IN THE CHILI.
YES, SIR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
NOW THIS PROCESS HERE, GUY,
IS GONNA TAKE ABOUT AN HOUR.
COOK IT DOWN.
THEN WE'RE GONNA STRAIN OFF
ALL THE EXCESS.
THE EXCESS FAT.
YES, SIR. I LIKE
TO LEAVE A LITTLE IN THERE.
FAT'S FLAVOR.
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT,
AFTER THE MEAT'S BROWNED,
I'M GONNA ADD TWO CANS
OF DICED TOMATOES,
A CAN
OF DARK KIDNEY BEANS.
THEN I'M GONNA ADD
THREE STICKS OF BUTTER,
SEASONED SALT, CHILI POWDER,
SALT, GARLIC POWDER,
A CUP OF KETCHUP,
THE HOT SAUCE.
OKAY,
STIRRING IT UP HERE, GUY.
LET IT COOK DOWN
FOR ABOUT TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
NOW TIME
TO MAKE THE BURGER.
HERE'S ONE RIGHT HERE.
GRILL IS NICE AND HOT.
GIVE IT A LITTLE SALT. THESE ARE
ACTUALLY 2/5 OF A POUND.
NOT FISTS BUT 2/5.
WELL, THAT'S .400
BATTING AVERAGE FOR BASEBALL.
ALL RIGHT, IT'S ABOUT
MEDIUM RARE RIGHT NOW.
I'M GONNA ADD THE CHEESE TO IT,
A LITTLE AMERICAN.
THAT'S HOW YOU GET THAT CHEESE
MELTED THERE, BOSS.
THERE IT IS.
BEAUTIFUL.
OKAY.
GOT A LITTLE CHILI
READY TO GO.
OKAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
THROW SOME DICED ONIONS
ON THERE, BUD,
HEALTHY AMOUNT OF JALAPEÑOS,
AND THIS IS A COMBO.
ONION RING AND FRIES?
YEP.
SHOULD I JUST
GET IN THERE?
WELL, THERE'S TWO TECHNIQUES--
FORK AND KNIFE
OR JUST GET AT IT.
AND YOU LOOK LIKE
A GET-AT-IT GUY.
LOOK AT THE JUICE
RUNNING OFF OF THAT.
YEAH, BROTHER.
CUT ME, MICK, CUT ME.
THERE YOU GO, YEAH.
THE CHILI'S ON POINT.
THE ONIONS ARE THERE.
LOVE THE JALAPEÑO.
A LITTLE BIT ON THE JUICY SIDE.
BUT DON'T LET ME BE THE JUDGE.
YOU COME CHECK IT OUT.
SO TELL ME ABOUT
THE CHILI CHEESEBURGER.
DELICIOUS.
THE CHEESE IS OOZING OUT.
CHILI CHEESEBURGERS.
(man) JUST THE TOMATO SAUCE
AND THE CHEESE AND EVERYTHING
IS JUST ALL MARINATED TOGETHER.
IT JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
SO THERE'S ENOUGH VARIETY,
AND THE QUALITY'S THE RIGHT WAY
THAT YOU COULD COME HERE
A COUPLE TIMES IN A DAY?
YEAH, EASY.
BECAUSE HE'S SERVING UP
ALL KINDS OF OPTIONS--
BURGERS, DOGS, AND MORE THAN
A DOZEN SANDWICHES.
HOW IS THE CUBAN SANDWICH
HERE?
I LOVE IT.
IT'S TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
BECAUSE ON DANNY'S
CUBAN SANDWICH,
HE THROWS IN ONE OF MY FAVORITE
ITALIAN MEATS--CAPOCOLLA.
AND IT ALL STARTS
WITH HIS HOUSE-MADE MOJO SAUCE.
START IT OFF, BROTHER.
THIS IS SOME FERMENTED O.J.,
FRESH LEMON JUICE,
A COUPLE SEEDS IN THERE--
A LITTLE TEXTURE--
RED ONION, ROASTED GARLIC--
WE ROAST OUR OWN HERE--
OREGANO, BAY LEAVES,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
NOW TAKE THIS BAD BOY HERE,
GIVE IT A FEW SHAKES.
SHAKIN' IT HERE BOSS.
SHAKIN' IT.
DID I JUST GET
A LITTLE "COOL HAND LUKE"?
THANK YOU.
DID I JUST GET
A LITTLE "COOL HAND LUKE"?
YEAH, YOU DID.
THAT'S IT, BUDDY.
SO YOU'LL LET THIS SIT HERE
AND MARINATE FOR A LITTLE BIT?
I LIKE TO DO IT A WEEK.
AND THEN THIS IS GONNA GO
ONTO THE PORK BUTT?
YOU GOT IT.
SO BONE-IN PORK BUTT.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA POUR THIS
OVER THE PORK BUTT?
NOW HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA
MARINATE ON THE PORK BUTT?
A DAY.
THE LAST THING I DO,
DRIED OREGANO,
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT ON TOP,
AND THAT'S THE LAST TOUCH.
AFTER WE MARINATE IT FOR 24,
I'LL PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
COVERED?
NO.
NO?
NO, SIR. I LIKE IT TO GET
A LITTLE CRUNCHY ON THE BLUBBER.
OKAY, JUST BECAUSE WE'RE
DOWN IN FLORIDA,
DOESN'T MEAN
YOU CAN CALL IT BLUBBER.
OKAY, IT'S PORK FAT,
EXCUSE ME.
THERE YOU GO.
AND HOW LONG IS THIS GONNA COOK?
THAT'S A LOW-AND-SLOW
FOR TEN HOURS.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
COOKED DOWN, NICE CRUST.
DAN, I'M JUST
DOING THIS FOR SCIENCE.
I REALLY
DON'T PICK IT.
OH, NO PROBLEM.
SUPER JUICY.
HOW DO WE BREAK INTO THIS?
WE'RE JUST GONNA
TEAR IT UP, BUDDY.
PEOPLE LIKE A LITTLE BLUBBER
ON THEIR SANDWICH,
A LITTLE CRUNCHY TEXTURE.
A LITTLE BLUBBER.
AND THEN WE'LL MAKE
THE SANDWICH FROM THIS.
WE'LL MAKE THE CUBAN
RIGHT FROM HERE.
WE BETTER MAKE
THE SANDWICH,
BECAUSE I'M GONNA
EAT ALL THIS RIGHT HERE.
LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT, I GOT
THE CUBAN BREAD.
WE'RE GONNA GO WITH
SOME MUSTARD AND SOME MAYO.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD THE PORK.
THEN I GOT VIRGINIA-BAKED HAM,
CAPOCOLLA,
WHICH IS PART OF THE DIFFERENCE
THAT WE DO AT DANNY'S,
SOME GOOD GENOA SALAMI,
SWISS CHEESE,
THEN SOME GOOD
NEW YORK DILL PICKLES.
NOW I CUT IT IN QUARTERS.
WRAP IT, PUT IT ON THE PRESS.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
I'D SAY
ABOUT THREE MINUTES.
OH, YEAH, YOU CAN FEEL
THE CRUNCH IN THE TOAST.
IT'S READY TO GO.
LOOK AT THAT.
WHOO, WHOO.
OH, WHAT YOU GET
IS CUBAN THANKSGIVING
IN A SANDWICH.
THAT'S IT.
OH.
THE BREAD IS SO NICE AND LIGHT
BUT BUILDS SUCH A GREAT CRUNCH,
TANG OF THE PICKLE,
TANG OF THE MUSTARD,
SWEETNESS OF THE HAM,
SPICINESS, A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CAPOCOLLA,
AND THEN YOU GET
THE MOJO PORK.
I MEAN, EVERYBODY'S
AT THE PARTY, MAN.
I JUST NEED A LITTLE TITO PUENTE
IN THE BACKGROUND,
AND I'D BE SET.
YOU WANT IT?
HE HAS IT.
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF CUBAN SANDWICHES.
YOU ROCKED IT OUT.
THANK YOU, BUDDY.
HI, GUYS.
DANNY'S FAMOUS CUBAN.
(man)
AN EXCELLENT CUBAN SANDWICH.
THE JUICES ALL FLOW TOGETHER.
THAT CAPOCOLLA
ADDS AN EXTRA BITE.
I LIKE THE SWEET HAM FLAVOR.
IN THE WORLD
OF CUBAN SANDWICHES,
YOU'D GIVE THIS
AN "A"?
I'D GIVE IT
THE STATE OF MIAMI APPROVAL.
THAT'S, LIKE, THE STATE BIRD
IN MIAMI IS THE CUBAN SANDWICH.
MM-HMM.
THIS IS WHERE I COME,
RIGHT TO DANNY'S.
I CAN'T GET
ENOUGH OF THE FOOD.
IT'S PREPARED EXACTLY
THE WAY YOU WANT IT.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU WANT.
IF SOMEONE COMES IN HERE,
AND THEY WANT TO HAVE SOMETHING
MADE SPECIAL THEIR WAY...
SURE.
DO YOU MAKE IT?
YEAH, ALL THE TIME.
NO QUESTIONS.
THROW A PATTY DOWN.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE GUY FIERI TRIPLE "D" BURGER
AT DANNY'S ALL-AMERICAN DINER
& DAIRY BAR.
DON'T GO ANYWHERE,
SERIOUSLY.
ALL RIGHT, WELCOME BACK.
HERE WE ARE AT TAMPA
HANGING OUT WITH DANNY
DANNY'S ALL-AMERICAN DINER
& DAIRY BAR.
NOW WE ARE MAKING THE TRIPLE "D"
TRIPLE PLAY.
IT'S ALL ABOUT BASEBALL HERE.
THIS IS MY BURGER.
ALL RIGHT, SO YOU'RE
GONNA GO BURGER DOWN,
PASTRAMI, A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CUBAN PORK.
THERE WE ARE.
THROW A COUPLE PIECES OF SWISS
CHEESE ON TOP OF THAT BURGER.
NOW I WANT SOMETHING
LIKE A SOURDOUGH BREAD.
I WANT TO DO
A PANINI ON THIS.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE TOASTING THE INSIDE,
BECAUSE WE'RE GONNA BE TOASTED
THE OUTSIDE WHEN IT GOES
IN THE PANINI PRESS.
OKAY.
SO FAR, SO GOOD, HUH?
IT LOOKS GOOD.
BREAD'S TOASTED,
DO A LITTLE BIT OF MUSTARD.
I THINK BOTH SIDES,
JUST A TOUCH LIKE THAT, RIGHT?
BURGER DOWN,
PASTRAMI ON TOP OF THAT.
LOOKING GOOD.
PORK ON TOP OF THAT.
TRIPLE PLAY, THREE MEATS,
TRIPLE "D," YOU SEE ME
HUN-GR-Y.
A COUPLE ONION RINGS, WHY NOT?
JUST THROW ON A TOMATO
AND SOME
OF THOSE JALAPEÑOS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT LOOKS GOOD.
A LITTLE AMERICAN ON TOP
OF THAT. PUT IT ALL TOGETHER.
OKAY.
LET'S THROW IT
IN THE PANINI PRESS.
OKAY.
OH, THAT'S A MONSTER.
IT CAN BARELY
HANDLE IT.
OH, YEAH, LOOKING GOOD.
OH, LOOK AT
THE SIZE OF THAT.
DO YOU WANT
TO CUT 'ER IN HALF?
SURE.
THE PASTRAMI,
TWO KINDS OF CHEESE,
JALAPEÑOS, TOMATOES,
AND ONION RINGS
ALL PUT TOGETHER--
GET ON SOME OF THAT, BOSS.
YOUR TRIPLE "D."
UNBELIEVABLE, BUDDY.
NO, SERIOUSLY.
THE PASTRAMI--
YOU GET THE PEPPER OUT OF THAT,
THE JUICINESS OF THE BURGER,
THE MOJO WITH THE PORK,
THEN A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
JALAPEÑO COMING THROUGH
WITH THE CRUNCHY BREAD...
MM-HMM.
DOUBLE CHEESE,
A TOUCH OF MUSTARD.
OH...
(speaking indistinctly)
TRIPLE "D" TRIPLE PLAY.
I LIKE IT.
OUT OF THE PARK, BABY.
BEAUTIFUL.
(woman) IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU GET THE FLAVOR
OF THE DIFFERENT MEATS,
AND THEN YOU HAVE THE JALAPEÑOS
FOR A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE TO IT.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING
OVER THERE?
IT'S CALLED
THE TRIPLE "D."
ARE YOU GONNA BE ABLE
TO GET IT ALL DOWN?
I'M DOING
THE BEST I CAN.
(laughs)
(man) REALLY GOOD SANDWICH.
A LITTLE MESSY, BUT THAT COMES
WITH A GOOD PLACE LIKE THIS.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES
TO EAT.
IT HAS THE ALL-AMERICAN FEEL
WITH THE BASEBALL
AND EVERYTHING.
THE MENU'S VERY ECLECTIC.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
GOOD TIME, DANNY.
THANKS FOR LETTING ME HANG.
THANK YOU, BUDDY.
YOU GOTTA COME MEET THIS GUY.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE HIM.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WHERE DO YOU WANT TO GO
WITH THIS NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
JUST GO, MAN.
(laughter)