HEY, EVERYBODY. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU GUYS GOTTA
TRY THIS.
WE'RE ON THE HUNT FOR THE BEST
THING BETWEEN SLICED BREAD.
DO THE VOODOO
THAT YOU DO.
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS...
PUERCO, PUERCO,
PUERCO.
THE SANDWICH SHOP...
WHEW.
GOING ALL OUT...
THIS MIGHT BE
THE BEST.
THANK YOU.
EVEN WHEN THEY'RE
BORROWING MY STYLE.
KNUCKLE SANDWICH?
THAT'S MY LINE.
IN LAS VEGAS, NEVADA,
THE N'AWLINS JOINT...
WHEW. NOTHIN' WRONG
WITH THAT.
SHARING THEIR LOVE
OF A BIG EASY CLASSIC.
I THINK I'M WEARING
HALF OF IT.
AND IN ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA...
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN. WHAT DO WE GOT?
I'M DROPPING IN ON ONE
OF MY ALL-TIME FAVES,
WHERE THEY'VE GOT
A NEW STORY...
YOU REBUILT THE WHOLE
ENTIRE PLACE?
AND SOME NEW BURGERS.
THIS IS THE GUY'S BIG BITE?
OR "THE DIVE,"
IN QUOTATIONS, RIGHT?
MMM.
ANY QUESTIONS?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN LAS VEGAS, RIGHT
NEXT TO CHARLESTON BOULEVARD,
ALMOST SMACK-DAB BETWEEN
DOWNTOWN AND THE STRIP.
NOW THIS BUILDING BEHIND ME
USED TO BE HOLSUM BAKERY.
IT'S HERE SINCE THE '50s
SERVING LAS VEGAS.
WELL, IN 2002 IT CLOSED,
BUT IT LEFT A VACANT SPOT
FOR A LOUISIANA NATIVE
TO FULFILL A LIFELONG DREAM.
THIS IS LOLA'S.
OH, IT'S TOTALLY
NEW ORLEANS.
IT'S FOOD SO GOOD IT'LL MAKE
A MAN WRITE BAD CHECKS.
SHE COULD PACK THIS UP
AND MOVE IT TO NEW ORLEANS,
IT'D BE PACKED
EVERY NIGHT.
BUT THE WHOLE POINT OF OPENING
THIS JOINT IN 2009
WAS FOR LOUISIANA NATIVE
LOLA POKORNY
TO BRING THE BIG EASY
TO SIN CITY.
EVERYTHING THAT
YOU'RE GONNA USE,
YOU'RE BRINGING
FROM NEW ORLEANS?
WE BRING FROM NEW ORLEANS
OR MAKE IT OURSELVES.
YOU WROTE ALL THE RECIPES?
YES.
RECIPES STRAIGHT OUT
OF THE FRENCH QUARTER,
LIKE A SPICY SHRIMP CREOLE...
SHRIMP CREOLE IS EXCELLENT.
A SEAFOOD-PACKED GUMBO...
GUMBO!
(bell dings)
AND THIS N'AWLINS CLASSIC,
THE PO'BOY.
THE ROAST BEEF PO'BOY HERE
IS FANTASTIC.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA DO
A ROAST BEEF DEBRIS,
BUT WE'RE THINKING ABOUT
CALLING IT "DA BREES."
'CAUSE IT'S WINDY
IN THIS AREA?
NO.
'CAUSE OF DREW.
GOOD GUY.
OKAY, SO HOW
DO WE MAKE IT?
WE HAVE A WHOLE
INSIDE ROUND,
AND WE'RE GONNA
SALT HIM UP REAL GOOD,
GONNA ADD SOME PEPPER.
GIVE HIM A LITTLE MASSAGE.
AND I'M GONNA ADD
A LITTLE WATER TO THE PAN
AND PUT SOME FOIL ON HIM,
AND WE'RE GONNA ROAST HIM
FOR ABOUT 12 HOURS.
RENDER IT ALL DOWN,
AND THIS SHOULD JUST BE SHRED,
PULL-APART, FORK-TENDER.
YES.
AND THEN FROM THERE?
I'LL TAKE
THE RENDERINGS,
AND I'LL MAKE A GRAVY.
AND IF YOU'RE GONNA
DO GRAVY,
I MEAN, DO IT LIKE THIS.
USE THAT RENDERED FAT.
SO THE FAT'S MOVIN'.
TIME FOR THE FLOUR.
AND I LIKE TO SEASON MY FLOUR
NOW. SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS COOK
JUST A COUPLE MORE MINUTES.
COOKED OUT THE FLOUR, WE GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR ON IT.
WE'RE READY TO GO. WE DON'T
USE WATER. WE USE OUR AU JUS.
AND THAT'S GONNA GET POURED OVER
THE SHREDDED BEEF IN THE PO'BOY?
IN THE PO'BOY.
WHEW. NOTHIN' WRONG
WITH THAT.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT
THE SHREDDED BEEF...
YES.
AND ON TO
THE BEAUTIFUL BAGUETTE.
WHOSE BREAD?
LEIDENHEIMER'S BREAD
OUT OF NEW ORLEANS.
MMM,
THAT'S THE ONLY ONE.
SO WHAT DO WE DO?
WE TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN STOCK
IN OUR PAN.
JUST ENOUGH TO ADD SOME MOISTURE
SO WE CAN HEAT THE MEAT.
YES.
WHILE THAT'S HEATING UP,
YOU DO THE BUN?
YES, SIR.
WE BUTTER HIM UP,
AND WE TOAST IT,
GET A GOOD CRUNCH ON HIM.
MAYONNAISE
AND SOME CREOLE MUSTARD...
ALL RIGHT.
AND SOME TOMATO
AND SOME LETTUCE.
SALT AND PEPPER.
AND THE MEAT
AND THEN THE GRAVY.
YES.
I THINK I'M WEARING
HALF OF IT.
THANK GOODNESS THIS
SHIRT'S THE SAME COLOR.
I LIKE IT. GRAVY'S NICE
AND TIGHT. NOT TOO THIN.
DOESN'T SNEAK IN THERE
AND MESS UP THE COLD VEGGIES.
YOU KNOW THE--I THINK,
MY FAVORITE PART OF IT IS
THE FACT THAT YOU BRING
THE BREAD IN FROM NEW ORLEANS.
IT'S GOT GOOD CHEW,
BUT IT'S LIGHT,
SOAKS UP THE JUICES.
ON POINT.
OH, I LOVE IT BECAUSE
OF THE JUICE JUST ROLLIN' OUT,
THE GRAVY, YOU KNOW.
THE MEAT IS TENDER
AND SOFT AND SPICY.
IT JUST SCREAMS
NEW ORLEANS.
IT'S A CAJUN
KITCHEN FOR SURE,
BUT THEY HAVE A LITTLE BIT
OF EVERYTHING.
LIKE THE SHRIMP AND GRITS...
SHE PUTS GOUDA IN 'EM,
SO THEY'RE A LITTLE SMOKY.
IT'S MY FAVORITE
THING HERE.
OR THE IN-HOUSE OYSTER BAR.
AND IF YOU THOUGHT MARDI GRAS
WAS THE NEW ORLEANS PARTY,
WELL, THEN YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
TO A CRAWFISH BOIL.
CRAWFISH UP!
(bell dings)
TELL ME ABOUT
CRAWFISH BOIL.
WHAT'S THE BEST PART
OF IT.
THE WHOLE EXPERIENCE.
YOU HAVE EVERYBODY SITTING
AROUND A TABLE EATING CRAWFISH.
I LEARNED HOW TO DO IT HERE,
'CAUSE I WAS, LIKE,
THE VIRGIN CRAWFISH EATER,
I'D NEVER SEEN IT.
CRACK THE TAIL
AND BREAK IT OFF.
YOU CAN DRINK A BEER
AND GET ANOTHER ONE.
SO LET'S GET STARTED.
WE GOT A BIG POT OF HOT WATER.
YOU'LL SALT IT FIRST.
YES.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA PUT IN TWO BAGS
OF ZATARAIN'S.
MY FAVORITE CRAB BOIL.
CAYENNE.
A LOT OF IT.
(whistles)
GARLIC. NEXT UP...
IS MY LOUISIANA
CRAWFISH COMPANY SEASONING.
THIS IS CALLED
LOLA'S TRASH POT.
BUT THE CELERY AND THE ONIONS
AND THE LEMONS
ARE JUST FOR THE FLAVOR
PIECE OF IT.
ALL FLAVOR.
YOU'RE NOT PUTTING THAT OUT
ON THE TRAY AND EATING IT.
NO.
NOW WE GO WITH
SOME BABY REDS.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IN BUTTER.
SO THE FAT--
THE OIL IN THERE
IS GOING TO MAKE IT
SO THE SHELLS
COME OFF EASIER
ON THE CRAWFISH.
YES.
LET THIS SIMMER FOR WHAT,
ANOTHER 20 MINUTES?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
WHAT'S UP NEXT?
CRAWFISH.
ANGRY LITTLE ONE,
HUH?
YEP.
HOW MANY POUNDS
WAS THIS?
THIS IS ABOUT
5 1/2 POUNDS.
AND THIS WILL FEED
HOW MANY FOLKS?
ME.
AND YOU CAN REALLY EAT
5 POUNDS OF THIS?
EVERY DAY.
NOW HOW LONG ARE THE CRAWFISH
GONNA COOK FOR?
ABOUT EIGHT MINUTES.
SO WHEN DO WE PUT
THE CORN IN?
RIGHT BEFORE YOU PULL
YOUR CRAWFISH,
YOU LIKE TO FLOAT
YOUR CORN.
AND WHO'D YOU
LEARN THIS FROM?
MY MOM AND DAD DID IT,
MY BROTHERS.
WE USED TO GO CRAWFISHING
ALL THE TIME. WE'RE READY.
DO I HAVE TO PUT 'EM ON THERE
WHILE IT'S SPINNING?
WHILE IT'S SPINNING--
THAT'LL BE THE FUN OF IT.
YOU COULD EAT ALL THIS?
YES. NOT ALL THE CORN
AND POTATOES,
BUT EVERY SINGLE
CRAWFISH.
OH.
NOW I'M GONNA JUST TOP IT OFF
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SEASONING.
YOU WANT A LESSON?
I KNOW THE TWIST
AND POP.
THERE YOU GO.
MMM. TASTY.
THE AMOUNT OF SEASONING
YOU DID--THIS IS NICE.
I MEAN, I WOULDN'T SAY THIS
IS A MILD BOWL, BY ANY MEANS.
CRAWFISH ARE
REALLY BUTTERY.
I JUST MEAN IN THE SENSE
THAT THEY'RE NICE AND TENDER.
MMM. WOW. YOU THINK
THAT TAIL MEAT'S SWEET,
THAT CLAW MEAT'S
OUT-OF-BOUNDS.
MMM. REALLY TASTY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
THEY'RE AWESOME. SLIPPERY LITTLE
SUCKERS, BUT THEY'RE AWESOME.
(Guy) DO YOU EAT
THE CORN AND THE POTATOES?
MM-HMM. THAT'S
THE BEST PART,
'CAUSE THEY ALL SUCK IN
THE SEASONING, TOO. IT'S SPICY.
SO HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
TO PEOPLE WHEN YOU SAY
"I'M GOING TO A CRAWFISH BOIL"--
PEOPLE GET FREAKED OUT?
THEY GET TOTALLY
FREAKED OUT.
I DIG THAT.
LOLA'S HAS BECOME,
IN A VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME,
A LOCAL INSTITUTION.
WE LIVED IN NEW ORLEANS
FOR 19 YEARS,
AND SO OUT IN VEGAS, YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR SOMETHING CLOSE,
UH, THIS PLACE
COMPARES TREMENDOUSLY.
(Guy) PEOPLE GOTTA
BE THRILLED.
NOT EVERYBODY GETS TO MAKE IT
TO NEW ORLEANS,
BUT A LOT OF FOLKS
DO COME TO VEGAS,
SO IF YOU COME TO VEGAS AND YOU
CAN KIND OF GET A DOUBLE DIP,
YOU GET A LITTLE NEW ORLEANS
EXPERIENCE AT THE SAME TIME.
NICE GOIN'.
THANK YOU.
FOR SOME REASON,
I CAN'T STOP EATIN' 'EM.
UP NEXT...
WHEW.
WE'RE HEADED
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS...
OH, THAT'S EPIC.
WHERE A FUNKY
SANDWICH SHOP...
WE LOOK FOR
THE RESPONSE TO BE,
"THAT'S THE BEST SANDWICH
I'VE EVER HAD."
IS GOING GANGSTER GOURMET.
OKAY, SO REGULAR PASTRAMI
IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
YOU HAVE TO ADD DUCK TO IT?
WE GOTTA KICK IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
SO HERE I AM ABOUT 20 MINUTES
NORTH OF DOWNTOWN AUSTIN
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT WHERE
TWO DUDES ARE HOUSE BUTCHERING,
SMOKING, CURING, BRINING
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING
YOU'D NEED FOR A SANDWICH.
WHAT REALLY GOT
MY ATTENTION, THOUGH,
IS THAT ONE OF THEIR MENU ITEMS
IS CALLED...
(record needled scratches)
A KNUCKLE SANDWICH.
KNUCKLE SANDWICH?
THAT'S MY LINE.
THIS IS THE NOBLE PIG.
IT'S NOBLE,
BUT IT'S KNOWN AS THE PIG.
JUST THE PIG.
WHERE YOU GOING TONIGHT?
GOING TO THE PIG.
THE PIG.
I'M HERE THREE TIMES A WEEK,
AT LEAST.
IS THERE AN ASSOCIATION,
A WORLD ORDER OF NOBLE PIG?
DO YOU GUYS HAVE
"McMEETINGS"? I MEAN...
NAH, FOR NOW,
THE PIG MAFIA
IS JUST BRANDON MARTINEZ
AND JOHN BATES,
TWO CATS WHO MET UP
IN CULINARY SCHOOL
AND WANTED TO GET SERIOUS
ABOUT SANDWICHES.
WE LOOK FOR
THE RESPONSE TO BE,
"THAT'S THE BEST SANDWICH
I'VE EVER HAD."
THE B.L.T.
THAT'S PHENOMENAL.
WHAT ELSE SHOULD
I TRY HERE?
THE SMOKED DUCK PASTRAMI.
IT'S AWESOME.
OKAY, LET'S GO, GUYS.
OH, THAT'S EPIC.
(laughter)
THIS IS HOW WE SHOOT
TRIPLE "D" NOW.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR DUCK PASTRAMI TODAY.
DUCK PASTRAMI?
YEP.
OKAY, SO REGULAR PASTRAMI
IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH,
YOU HAVE
TO ADD DUCK TO IT?
WE GOTTA KICK IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS ONE
OF OUR TOP SELLERS.
SO YOU BRING IN
THE WHOLE DUCK?
WE BRING IN
THE WHOLE DUCK.
AND WE'RE GONNA
DO WHAT WITH THIS?
WE'RE GONNA BREAK
THAT GUY DOWN.
I MEAN, BREAK IT DOWN,
LIKE...
BREAK IT DOWN,
JUST TEAR IT ALL TO PIECES.
OH, OKAY. LET'S DO
THE VOODOO THAT YOU DO.
SPICE RUB?
SPICE RUB.
KOSHER SALT,
SOME SUGAR,
CORIANDER, BAY LEAF,
BLACK PEPPER,
AND MY FAVORITE INGREDIENT
IN THE WORLD, ALLSPICE.
SERIOUSLY?
YEP, I LOVE THOSE KIND OF
LICORICE-Y FLAVORS.
THIS GUY WE JUST SEASON UP,
FLIP IT OVER.
WE TIE IT UP NEXT, AND THEN
THROW IT IN THE SMOKER.
HOW LONG?
SIX HOURS.
THEN WE TAKE IT OUT,
LET IT COOL.
THAT IS, OH, NICE
AND THIN, HUH?
THAT'S CRAZY. YOU JUST KEEP
SLICING YOUR LITTLE HEART OUT.
I'M GONNA EAT
ALL OF THAT. MMM.
I'VE HAD A LOT OF DUCK PASTRAMI.
THIS MIGHT BE THE BEST.
THANK YOU.
IT'S ALL THE COMPONENTS
YOU WANT IN PASTRAMI,
BUT WITH DUCK, SO YOU GET
THE RICHNESS OF IT. WHEW.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
WE PUT A LITTLE
HEAT ON IT.
AND THEN THAT'S GONNA
GET SERVED ON?
YOUR CHOICE OF TOASTED
WHITE OR WHEAT BREAD.
YOU GUYS BAKE
THE BREAD AS WELL?
WE BAKE IT FRESH DAILY.
VERY NICE.
TOASTED BREAD.
A LITTLE BIT
OF RUSSIAN DRESSING.
I MEAN, IS IT REALLY P.C.
TO CALL IT RUSSIAN ANYMORE?
IT'S COMMIE DRESSING.
WE'RE IN TEXAS.
SO YOU DIDN'T HEAT IT UP
TOO MUCH.
NO.
(whistles)
I KNEW YOU WERE LEAVING
YOURSELF A LITTLE SNACK.
GET IT BACK ON MINE.
GOTTA HAVE A LITTLE BIT
FOR THE CHEF.
THE JUICE. AND THE PAN
AS A SOUVENIR.
I'M JUST KIDDING.
OKAY.
THESE ARE THE RYE PICKLES.
RYE PICKLES?
RYE PICKLES.
PUT THE LID ON IT,
AND CUT IT.
WHA!
THAT'S DARN GOOD DUCK.
THAT IS THE PERFECT BALANCE.
THE SALT, THE SMOKE,
THE TENDERNESS, IT'S COOKED
DOWN THE WAY IT SHOULD.
THE FAT MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT'S AWESOME.
YOU GUYS GOTTA TRY THIS.
WHAT ARE YOU
ENJOYING?
THE DUCK PASTRAMI
SANDWICH.
OOH, PHENOMENAL.
YEAH.
SOMEONE'S BRINGING GOURMET
SANDWICHES TO YOUR BACKYARD.
ABSOLUTELY.
EVERYTHING HERE IS HOMEMADE,
FROM THE BREAD
TO THE MEATS
TO THE MUSTARD.
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT THE PENDING
LAWSUIT OF THE KNUCKLE SANDWICH.
DID YOU KNOW THAT THEY, UH,
FULL-ON RIPPED OFF MY NAME?
NO.
YEAH, YEAH.
WELL, WE HAD TO TAKE--
YOU CAN CALL IT THE GUY FIERI
TRIBUTE SANDWICH,
I MEAN, I'M FINE
WITH THAT.
SOMETHING LONG AND ELABORATE,
MAYBE WITH A PICTURE.
OKAY. ALL RIGHT,
SO THIS IS THE KNUCKLE.
IT'S A GREAT CUT OF MEAT.
IT'S VERY TENDER.
SO BASICALLY WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS GONNA RUB IT DOWN,
STARTING OFF WITH
A LITTLE SALT ON THIS BAD BOY.
WE'VE GOT PEPPER ON THERE
AND THEN THE GRANULATED
GARLIC THERE.
WE THROW A LITTLE
EARL ON THERE.
DID YOU JUST SAY "EARL"?
A LITTLE EARL.
OKAY.
AND, UH, WE'RE GONNA POP IT
IN THE OVEN, 400 DEGREES,
FOR ABOUT, YOU KNOW,
AN HOUR AND A HALF OR SO.
OKAY.
MEDIUM-RARE.
MEDIUM-RARE, SIR.
LET IT COOL.
LOOK AT THAT.
COMING BEHIND.
SHARP.
MMM.
LEAN, MEAN,
AND TENDER.
THE KNUCKLE'S DONE, AND NOW
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE JUS FOR IT.
WE ADD A LITTLE WATER
TO THE PAN HERE, YOU KNOW,
PICK UP ALL THEM
GOOD DRIPPINGS,
GOTTA SCRAPE ALL THIS
GOOD STUFF UP.
WE ADD THE REST
OF OUR WATER HERE.
GOT OUR BEEF BONES
GOING IN.
THAT'S WHERE
ALL THE REAL FLAVOR.
THERE YOU GO. SEASON IT UP
WITH SOME SALT, PEPPER,
DRIED THYME HERE,
GRANULATED GARLIC, MAN.
RED WINE VIN. LET IT COOK FOR
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF OR SO.
SO WE'VE GOT
OUR KNUCKLE MEAT HERE.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS
ON THERE,
AND THEN TOPPING IT OFF
WITH SOME CHEDDAR CHEESE.
DO A NICE LADLE
OF THE HOT JUS IN THERE.
AND IN THE OVEN IT GOES.
WHITE BREAD HERE.
WE'RE GONNA DIP THE BREAD
IN THE JUS,
AND HIT THAT WITH SOME OF
THE KNUCKLE SAUCE HERE.
KNUCKLE SAUCE?
KNUCKLE SAUCE.
OUR HORSERADISH SAUCE.
YOU GUYS CAN'T CONTINUE
TO STEAL MY NAME.
CHEESE NICE AND MELTED
UP ON THE KNUCKLE SANDWICH.
TAKE THAT WHOLE BIG PILE,
JUST PLOP IT RIGHT
ON TOP OF THERE.
WELL, AT LEAST IT'S NOT ANY
LITTLE PETITE KNUCKLE SANDWICH.
THAT'S IT, MAN. GARNISH IT UP
WITH A LITTLE RYE PICKLE HERE,
SOME ONIONS,
A CARROT ON TOP,
NEED A FORK AND KNIFE,
AND YOU'RE READY TO DIG IN.
MM-MMM.
THE MEAT IS COOKED
PERFECTLY.
THE AU JUS HAS GOT REAL
BIG FLAVOR. IT'S DELICIOUS.
I NOW RECOGNIZE,
RESPECT,
AND DEEM THIS
APPROPRIATE
TO BE CALLED KNUCKLE SANDWICH.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GOING FOR,
SIR, AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'LL SEND
YOUR PLAQUE IN THE MAIL.
SO WE HAD GOOD LUCK
WITH THE DUCK.
WE RECOGNIZE
THE KNUCKLE SANDWICH,
AND WHEN WE COME BACK TO
THE NOBLE PIG HERE IN AUSTIN,
WE'RE DOING PIG
THREE WAYS.
WE'LL SEE YOU
IN A LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, WELCOME BACK
TO THE NOBLE PIG IN AUSTIN.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THESE GUYS ARE JUST ABOUT READY
TO PUT ME TO THE GROUND
WITH THESE SANDWICHES,
AND WE HAVE ONE MORE. IT'S PIG
THREE WAY--WHAT'S IT CALLED?
THE NOBLE PIG.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE A HAM,
WE'RE GONNA PULL PORK,
AND MAKE BACON, AND PUT IT
TOGETHER FOR A SANDWICH?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING
FIRST?
ALL RIGHT, SO THIS IS
A BRINE THAT WE'RE MAKING
FOR OUR HAM HERE
THAT'S GOING ON THE NOBLE.
WATER.
OUR SALT GOING IN.
ALL RIGHT,
WE HAVE OUR SUGAR.
A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
CARROTS, CELERY,
ONION.
OH, YEAH. NOW WE'VE GOT
OUR ALLSPICE GOING IN HERE.
A LITTLE
RED CHILI FLAKE.
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE BAY LEAF,
A LITTLE--LOT OF THYME.
PARSLEY,
BLACK PEPPERCORNS.
THIS BASICALLY
COMES UP TO A BOIL,
AND THEN INTO THE PAN.
IN THEY GO.
WHAT ARE WE DOING
WITH THIS,
CLEANING OUT
YOUR SINUSES?
UH, WE ARE GONNA INJECT IT
WITH THE BRINE.
KIND OF EXPEDITING
THE BRINING PROCESS.
YEAH, HELPING IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT,
YOU KNOW, WE DO LET IT
BRINE FOR FIVE DAYS.
FIVE DAYS LIKE THIS?
WOW.
FIVE DAYS LIKE THIS.
WE PULL IT OUT AND STICK
OUR HAM RUB ON THERE.
SO WE'VE GOT SALT,
SUGAR...
PEPPER GUY,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
SOME RED CHILI FLAKE, SOME
CHILI POWDER, AND SOME PAPRIKA.
SOME ANCHO POWDER IN THERE
AS WELL FOR THE LOVE.
AND THEN WE JUST
SEASON 'EM UP.
SO THIS GETS RUBBED
ON BOTH SIDES.
YEAH.
LIBERALLY DONE. BUT THIS IS JUST
ONE OF THE THREE COMPONENTS!
I WAS TRYING TO, LIKE,
MONSTER TRUCK WITH THAT.
SO THIS GOES TO THE OVEN--
45 MINUTES, 400 DEGREES.
YEAH. YEP.
(voice echoes) PUERCO,
PUERCO, PUERCO!
(voice echoes)
TODO LO DíA!
(wah-wah horn plays)
(sighs)
YET ANOTHER COMPONENT.
PORK BELLY. SO YOU MAKE--ALL
THE BACON THAT YOU GUYS DO HERE,
YOU GUYS CURE
AND DO YOURSELF?
ABSOLUTELY,
OH, YEAH.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
HOW ARE WE GONNA DO IT?
SEASON IT DOWN.
BACON CURE IS SALT, BROWN SUGAR,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
BAY LEAVES, BLACK PEPPER.
RUB IT DOWN.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA
LET IT SALT CURE...
YEAH.
THEN YOU'RE GONNA TAKE IT,
SLICE IT, COOK IT TO ORDER.
THERE YOU GO.
WORD. NOW WHAT?
THE PORK SHOULDER.
SALT, PEPPER,
MUSTARD SEED,
AND OF COURSE, THE MIREPOIX
JUST KIND OF SPRINKLED ABOUT.
WHOLE GARLIC.
THAT'S IT.
WE COOK 'EM SLOW AND LOW
IN THE OVEN.
WE PUT IT AT 200 DEGREES, AND WE
GENERALLY COOK IT OVERNIGHT.
THIS IS IT RIGHT HERE.
OUR LITTLE SALT IN THERE.
THE MIREPOIX AND EVERYTHING'S
GONNA GO INTO THE--
YOU CAN'T THROW THAT OUT. THAT'S
GOOD TASTY NIBLETS RIGHT THERE.
GOOD TASTY NIBLETS?
WE HAVE HAM, WE HAVE
THE PULLED PORK, AND THE BACON?
AND THE BACON.
LET'S ROCK IT.
SHE'S READY TO ROCK. I'M
GONNA SLICE THIS BAD BOY UP.
SO THE HAM'S READY.
JUST TAKE
A HANDFUL--
TAKE A HANDFUL?
PULLED PORK HERE.
HAVE OUR PROVOLONE CHEESE GOING
RIGHT UP ON TOP OF THERE.
THAT'S READY FOR THE OVEN.
TOAST SOME BREAD.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW WE'VE GOT
OUR HOUSE-MADE MUSTARD HERE.
MAYONNAISE.
OH, YEAH. SOME OF THAT
HOUSE-CURED BACON.
THIS IS THE FINISHED PRODUCT
HERE FOR THE NOBLE PIG--
GOT THE HAM, THE PULLED PORK,
AND THE CHEESE.
IT'S OUTSTANDING, MAN.
THE HAM'S OUTSTANDING.
PULLED PORK'S SUPER TENDER.
YOU TIE IT ALL TOGETHER.
IT'S A TOTAL PIG THREE-WAY,
AND VERY WORTHY
OF ITS NAME.
EVERYTHING YOU GUYS DO,
THE TIME YOU TAKE,
THE ENERGY, THE ATTITUDE,
THE DEDICATION,
TYING IT ALL TOGETHER AND MAKING
OUTSTANDING ARTISAN SANDWICHES--
THAT'S WHAT TRIPLE "D"
IS ALL ABOUT.
MY MAN.
YEAH!
YIKES.
UP NEXT,
WE'RE HEADED TO
ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA...
KILLER.
TO HOOK UP WITH
SOME OLD FRIENDS.
I COME BACK
AND HANG OUT WITH YOU,
WE CAN DROP THIS THING
DOWN A FEW NOTCHES.
WHO ARE STILL
BURNING IT UP...
IT'S MEAT ON MEAT WITH
NO INTERRUPTION OF VEGGIE.
EVEN THOUGH THEY BURNT DOWN.
WE HAD A COUPLE
FIREFIGHTERS
THAT STEPPED OUTSIDE,
AND THEY SAID, "IT'S BAD."
BACK IN 2007, ONE OF THE FIRST
PLACES WE SHOT TRIPLE "D"
HERE IN ST. PAUL, MINNESOTA,
WAS AT THE NOOK.
YOU REMEMBER, TWO LOCAL BOYS
TAKE OVER THIS LONG-STANDING
BURGER-BAR JOINT,
AND JUST BLOW IT UP.
AND YOU GUYS LOVE THE PLACE.
WELL, THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
TRAGEDY--
THE PLACE BURNS DOWN.
SO IS IT OVER?
NO, IT AIN'T OVER.
IT AIN'T OVER UNTIL CASPER
AND RUNYON SAY IT'S OVER,
'CAUSE THIS IS
THE NEW AND IMPROVED NOOK.
WORKING ON A CHORIZO
RIGHT NOW.
JUICY NOOKIE,
FRIED ONIONS.
SO, GUYS, LET ME
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU TWO BUDDIES
TAKE OVER THE JOINT
THAT HAD BEEN
LONG-STANDING HERE,
TRIPLE "D" COMES IN...
AND ONE OF THE BEST IS AT THIS
JOINT, THE NOOK IN ST. PAUL.
YOU GUYS BLOW UP.
I REMEMBER GETTING SOME E-MAILS,
HOW BUSY YOU WERE,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN,
I GET A HORRIFIC E-MAIL--
PLACE BURNS DOWN.
DECEMBER 2010,
AN ELECTRICAL FIRE TURNED
THE TABLES ON THE BOYS.
RIGHT BEFORE CHRISTMAS,
THE 14th.
YOU GOTTA BE
KIDDING ME.
WE GOT THE PHONE CALL
ABOUT 4:00 IN THE MORNING...
RIGHT.
HEAD DOWN HERE,
IT'S BAD, YOU KNOW,
WE HAD A COUPLE
FIREFIGHTERS
THAT STEPPED OUTSIDE,
AND THEY SAID, YOU KNOW,
IT'S, UM, "IT'S NOT LOOKING
GOOD IN THERE."
IT WAS A TOTAL LOSS.
YEAH, IT WAS DEVASTATING.
IT WAS A HARD--HARD GO.
THESE DUDES DIDN'T EVEN BLINK.
AFTER SIX MONTHS
OF REBUILDING,
THEY'RE SMOKING
BEHIND THE GRILL.
SO YOU REBUILT
THE WHOLE ENTIRE PLACE?
YEAH. THE BAR'S
THE ORIGINAL BAR,
BACK BAR'S THE ORIGINAL BAR,
AND SOME OF THE STOOLS
THAT THE PEOPLE ARE
SITTING IN RIGHT NOW.
WHAT THE FIREFIGHTERS DID
IS THEY CAME THROUGH
THE WHOLE PLACE, TOOK
THE PICTURES OFF THE WALL
BEFORE THEY STARTED
CHOPPING AND SPRAYING.
SO A LOT OF WHAT YOU SEE
ON THE WALL TODAY IS, UH,
STUFF FROM THE ORIGINAL BAR,
WHICH IS GREAT.
IS THERE A FIREMAN'S
DISCOUNT ON DECEMBER 14th?
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
DECEMBER 14th, ALL
FIREFIGHTERS EAT FOR FREE.
AND TO GO WITH
THIS NEW SPACE...
ALL RIGHT,
GUY'S BIG BITE.
ONE SPANISH FLY,
TORTILLA CHIPS.
EVEN MORE STUFFED BURGERS.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
THE RUNDOWN. WHAT DO WE GOT?
WE'RE CALLING THIS ONE
THE SPANISH FLY.
IT'S A 50-50 BLEND OF OUR GROUND
BEEF AND A CHORIZO SAUSAGE,
STUFFED WITH
A QUESO FRESCO.
LOOK AT THIS.
THE ART OF STUFFING
A BURGER WITH CHEESE
IS NOT AS SIMPLE
AS IT LOOKS,
AND YOU GUYS MAKE IT LOOK
REAL EASY.
MMM.
ANY QUESTIONS?
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH
AN EASY RUNDOWN.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE,
NOT TOO MUCH,
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE GUAC,
A LITTLE CHEESE IN THE MIDDLE.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S THIS MONSTER?
THAT'S THE GUY'S BIG BITE
RIGHT THERE.
THIS IS THE GUY'S BIG BITE?
OR "THE DIVE,"
IN QUOTATIONS, RIGHT?
ITALIAN BEEF GOIN' ON.
GUY'S BIG BITE.
BACON, BURGER STUFFED
WITH PEPPER JACK CHEESE,
UH, ITALIAN BEEF,
CHEDDAR ON TOP.
IT'S MEAT ON MEAT WITH
NO INTERRUPTION OF VEGGIE.
SO THE CHEDDAR'S ON TOP OF THE
ROAST BEEF TO MATCH YOUR HAIR.
(laughs)
I GOT A HUNCH
ON THIS ONE.
OH, OH. THAT ITALIAN BEEF
ON THERE, MAN.
YEAH.
TWO KINDS OF CHEESE,
STUFFED BURGER.
THAT'S GOTTA BE A HIT.
I'M VERY PROUD OF YOU GUYS.
AWESOME. THANKS, MAN.
THANKS FOR STOPPING BY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
DYNAMITE.
ORDER UP!
WHAT DO THE
REGULARS THINK?
ARE THEY HAPPY WITH
THE NEW AND IMPROVED?
YEAH, I THINK
THEY LIKE IT.
YOU KNOW, THEY MISS
THE DIVE-INESS OF THE OLD NOOK,
BUT--
WELL, YOU TWO
ARE STILL HERE.
THAT'S DIVE-Y ENOUGH,
RIGHT, YEAH.
YEAH.
AND YOU GUYS
CAN'T--LISTEN,
I COME BACK
AND HANG OUT WITH YOU,
WE CAN DROP THIS THING
DOWN A FEW NOTCHES.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(voice echoes)
GENE SIMMONS...
EN LA COCINA!
(laughter)
WHAT DID THAT LOOK LIKE?
(man) RIDICULOUS.