HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(gong crash)
I'M GETTING TRADITIONAL TASTES
IN SOME UNUSUAL PLACES.
(laughter)
OKAY, STAY WITH ME NOW...
I'M GONNA BE FINE.
IN HONOLULU, HAWAII...
(whistles)
A JAMAICAN JOINT...
YEAH!
JERK-IFYING WINGS...
NOW IT'S KICKIN' IN.
THAT'S A GREAT WING.
AND GETTING
THEIR GOAT ON...
THERE'S SO MUCH GOATS
HERE IN HAWAII.
WELL, THEY'RE
MISSING ONE.
IN ARLINGTON, TEXAS...
SO START ME OFF.
THE RUSSIANS ARE COMING--I
SAID, THE RUSSIANS ARE COMING!
WE SHOULD DO A SPACE
STATION OR SOMETHING.
ACTUALLY, IT WAS
ALREADY DONE.
AND IT'S GONNA BE AWESOME.
NEXT YOU'RE GONNA TELL ME
WE'RE GONNA PUT
A MAN ON THE MOON.
OKAY.
AND IN LAS VEGAS,
A COLLEGE TACO BAR...
WHERE WERE YOU
WHEN I WENT TO SCHOOL?
WITH FLAVORS THAT HAVE A PhD
IN ROCK 'N' ROLL.
THAT'S NOT A REGULAR TACO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW ON TRIPLE "D,"
I GET TO VISIT SOME
OF THE COOLEST RESTAURANTS,
MEET SOME OF THE GREATEST CHEFS
AND TRY OUTRAGEOUS FOOD.
I GOTTA SAY, I DON'T KNOW THAT
WE HAVE ENOUGH REPRESENTATION
ON SOME OF THE GREATS,
LIKE LEBANESE,
TRINIDADIAN, BULGARIAN, OR ONE
OF MY ALL-TIME FAVORITES,
JAMAICAN, SO WHEN
I FLY INTO OAHU,
CRUISE OUTSIDE OF WAIKIKI,
YOU KNOW I'M STOKED
TO FIND THIS JOINT--
JAWAIIAN IRIE JERK.
HERE'S YOUR
JAMAICAN CURRY GOAT.
IT'S THIS GREAT CARIBBEAN
RESTAURANT,
BUT WITH A REAL
ALOHA FEELING.
A HAWAIIAN ATTITUDE THAT'S GOT
A JAMAICAN TRANSLATION.
IRIE.
UH, IRIE?
THAT MEANS ALOHA.
SOMETHING CHEF CASSIE SIMMONDS
BROUGHT WITH HIM
FROM HIS HOMELAND.
RUMOR HAS IT THAT
YOU WERE FRIENDS WITH
THE GREATEST REGGAE LEGEND.
YES, I USED TO PLAY SOCCER
IN THE BACKYARD OF BOB MARLEY,
BACK IN TRENCH TOWN.
OH, MY GOSH.
NO DREADS?
THE DREAD
IS IN THE HEART.
AND IN THE FOOD
HE WHIPS UP,
STARTING WITH
THE WEST INDIES CLASSICS.
THE GOAT, THE RICE AND PEAS,
THE ITAL STEW.
AND WHEN YOU THINK JAMAICAN,
YOU GOTTA THINK JERK SEASONING.
WE HAVE SOME JERK WINGS
AND FESTIVAL.
WE'RE GOING TO START
WITH SOME JERK MARINADE,
MAN, FOR THE WINGS.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME ONIONS,
FIRE IN YOUR WIRE.
FIRE IN YOUR WHAT?
FIRE IN YOUR WIRE
HOT SAUCE.
A BLEND OF CHILI
AND PEPPERS,
HAWAIIAN CHILI,
GHOST PEPPERS,
SCOTCH BONNETS,
AND SOME HERBS AND SPICES.
NOW IT'S KICKING IN.
NO, IT'S FANTASTIC.
(laughs)
IT'S A LOT BETTER NOW.
I'M GONNA BE FINE.
THAT'S A FIRST
FOR ME, MAN.
NEXT UP, WE HAVE
THE DRIED JERK SEASONING.
SO WE ADD IT.
(whistles)
THYME, THEN WE HAVE GARLIC.
CURRY.
YEAH.
SOY SAUCE, OIL,
AND LAST, WATER.
NOW OUR MARINADE
IS READY.
THIS IS THE DRY JERK.
CAN I TRY THIS?
YES, BOSS.
(whistles)
HOW LONG DO YOU LET
THE WINGS MARINATE?
SO I LET THEM MARINATE
OVERNIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, SO THE WINGS
ARE MARINATED.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT THEM
ONTO THE GRILL.
GREAT.
GET NICE SMOKY FLAVOR
AND A MARK ON THEM.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD?
USING SOME NICE
HICKORY CHIPS.
SMOKING AND COOKING
THE WINGS,
AND THEN FINISHING 'EM
IN THE OVEN.
WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS WITH
A DUMPLING WE CALL THE FESTIVAL.
IT'S A SWEETENED DOUGH. FESTIVAL
YOU'LL FIND ALL OVER JAMAICA.
REALLY?
LIKE, PARTY IN YOUR MOUTH?
YEAH, YOU FEEL HAPPY
WHEN YOU FINISH EATING IT.
REALLY, I THOUGHT
THAT WAS CALLED BEER.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD FLOUR.
A LITTLE CORNMEAL.
SO YOU'RE GONNA GET SOME
NICE TEXTURE OUT OF IT.
BROWN SUGAR, CINNAMON, THEN
WE ADD A LITTLE BAKING POWDER.
CARB-ING IT.
THEN WE HAVE
A LITTLE BAKING SODA.
THESE ARE GONNA PUFF UP
A LITTLE BIT.
WE HAVE A LITTLE SALT
FOR TASTE. NUTMEG, MAN.
NUTMEG.
MIX THIS UP
A LITTLE BIT.
MOST OF THE ISLANDS,
WE USE COCONUT MILK
INSTEAD OF USING HEAVY CREAM.
THEN WE'LL MIX A LITTLE.
THEN WE FINISH
WITH WATER.
GONNA PINCH A LITTLE
PIECE OF THE DOUGH,
WE'LL ROLL IT INTO,
LIKE, 4 INCHES LONG.
WE'RE MAKING
HUSH PUPPIES.
YOU JUST SIT THERE AND FRY
'EM UP, A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
YEAH, JAMAICAN STYLE,
WE CALL IT.
♪♪♪
SO WE JUST PUT A LITTLE
SAUCE ON THAT.
COME WITH OUR FESTIVAL.
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT OF CINNAMON.
NOT REALLY SWEET,
BUT IT'S ABOUT THE CONSISTENCY
OF A HUGH PUPPY.
THESE BAD BOYS--
MMM.
MMM! THE WING
IS SUPER TENDER.
YOU GET ALL THAT SPICE,
AND THEN YOU GET A LITTLE BITE
OF THE FESTIVAL, THEN YOU
GET SOME OF THE CRUNCH,
AND YOU GET SOME OF THE SWEET.
NOW YOU GET THIS CONTRAST GOING.
MAN, THAT IS A FESTIVAL.
BALANCE, BALANCE.
THAT'S A GREAT WING. MMM.
RESPECT, RESPECT.
JERK WINGS
AND FESTIVAL.
FLAVORS ARE AMAZING.
THE SPICES ARE GREAT.
AND CASSIE'S BRINGING IT
WITH MORE THAN JUST THE JERK.
HE'S TYING IN FLAVORS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
IN THE WEST INDIES,
YOU HAVE ABOUT FIVE OR SIX
RACES OF PEOPLE,
SORT OF BLEND
THE DISHES TOGETHER.
CURRY--
PART OF THE INDIAN DISH.
YOU CAN FIND IT IN THE CHICKEN,
AND IT'S SOMETHING YOU MIGHT
NOT EXPECT IN HAWAII.
JAMAICAN CURRY GOAT,
COMING AT YOU IN THE WINDOW.
ALL RIGHT,
SOME GOAT.
YES, MAN.
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
THE GOAT MEAT,
SO WE ADD A LITTLE
SOY SAUCE,
FIRE IN YOUR WIRE.
YES. A LITTLE GARLIC POWDER,
CHOPPED GARLIC,
CURRY POWDER,
ROSEMARY,
THYME, BASIL,
OREGANO.
YES, MAN.
ALLSPICE, MAKE IT NICE,
AND BAY LEAVES.
OKAY, SO MIX THIS ALL UP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA...
COOK THAT DOWN AFTER
FOR THREE HOURS.
THAT'S A LITTLE VOODOO
GOAT DANCE, MAN,
VOODOO GOAT DANCE.
WE'LL WRAP IT WITH PLASTIC
AND PUT IT IN THE REFRIGERATOR
TO MARINATE OVERNIGHT.
WE'VE GOT
MARINATED GOAT.
YES, MAN.
ADD A LITTLE OIL
TO OUR PAN HERE.
(sizzling)
AFTER IT GETS BROWN
AND CRISPY,
WE'LL ADD THE COCONUT MILK
AND THE WATER.
LET IT COOK
FOR TWO HOURS.
NOW ALL THE VEGGIES
GO IN.
CARROTS,
PEPPERS,
ONIONS,
SCALLIONS, CILANTRO,
CURRY POWDER, MAN.
ALL RIGHT, THEN WE HAVE
FIRE IN YOUR WIRE.
THIS IS YOUR WEIRD
SCOTCH BONNET DEVIL SALSA.
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP.
AND WE'RE GONNA
COOK THIS FOR HOW LONG?
FOR THREE HOURS
OR SO.
THE GOAT IS READY.
THAT'S LIKE A BOAT OF GOAT.
ALL ABOARD, HUH?
LOOK AT THAT.
TENDER GOAT.
OH.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
MMM. IF I MADE GOAT
LIKE THIS,
I'D GLOAT.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S TENDER, IT FALLS
RIGHT OFF THE HOOF.
NOT SPICY,
BUT SUPER FLAVORFUL.
MMM. I'M NOT KIDDING YA.
IT'S JUST THAT PHENOMENAL.
THEHERE IN HAWAII,ATS
ESPECIALLY IN MAUI
AND THE BIG ISLAND.
WELL, THEY'RE
MISSING ONE.
IS THIS LIKE YOU REMEMBER
IT FROM HOME?
I MEAN, THIS IS THE KIND
OF FOOD THAT--
YEAH, THAT THE OLD--
THE OLD PEOPLE COOKS.
MMM. THIS IS THE MAN
RIGHT HERE.
UP NEXT...
YOU'RE NOT
GETTING MARRIED
IF YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT 100
DISHES MADE FROM POTAT-ERS.
"POTAT-ERS"? THAT WAS SOME
OF THE TEXAS COMING OUT.
WE'RE HEADING
TO ARLINGTON, TEXAS...
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
FOR THE REAL-DEAL
RUSSIAN.
I'M RUSSIAN
RIGHT NOW--
RUSHIN' TO GET SOME
OF THIS IN MY MOUTH.
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE CAN ALL
PRETTY MUCH AGREE
THAT TEXAS IS SO BIG,
IT'S KIND OF LIKE A MELTING POT
OF CULTURES AND CUISINES.
NOW I'M IN ARLINGTON, JUST ABOUT
30 MILES OUTSIDE OF DALLAS,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT I--
I GUESS YOU COULD KIND OF CALL,
LIKE, THE EASTERN BLOCK
BONANZA EXTRAVAGANZA.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN'
RESTAURANT,
GROCERY,
AND RUSSIAN GIFTS.
THIS IS TASTE OF EUROPE.
CABBAGE ROLLS,
CHEESE BLINTZES.
IT'S JUST AUTHENTIC
EASTERN EUROPEAN COMFORT FOOD.
HUNGARIAN GOULASH.
IT'S ALL HOMEMADE,
AND IT'S TASTY.
AND THEIR MOTTO IS "SHOP WHILE
YOU EAT AND EAT WHILE YOU SHOP,"
SO THE GIFT STORE
IS A NICE COMBINATION.
BEEF-STROGANOFF.
YOU'VE BEEN TO RUSSIA, AND
YOU'RE SAYING THIS IS LEGIT.
JUST AS GOOD, IF NOT BETTER
THAN WHAT WE'VE GOT
WHEN WE'RE ACTUALLY
IN RUSSIA.
REALLY?
THAT'S BECAUSE OWNER
MICHAEL FRUMKIN
IMMIGRATED FROM RUSSIA,
BRINGING THE BEST
OF HIS HOMELAND TO TEXAS
WHEN HE OPENED THIS JOINT
IN '02.
CABBAGE ROLLS.
WITH HIS WIFE IRINA PAVLOVA
DISHING OUT
THE EASTERN BLOCK CUISINE.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
EASTERN EUROPE FOOD?
IT'S NOT THAT SPICY,
AND THERE'S LOTS
OF VEGETABLES.
SO YOUR FAVORITE ITEM
ON THE MENU?
UH, KOLDUNY.
(woman) IT'S POTATO PANCAKE
WITH A MEAT MIXTURE INSIDE.
DELICIOUS.
VERY TYPICAL
FOR THE PLACE
WHERE I WAS BORN,
IN BELARUS...
UH-HUH.
YOU'RE NOT
GETTING MARRIED
IF YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT 100
DISHES MADE FROM POTAT-ERS,
BECAUSE POTATOES IS--
DID YOU JUST
GIVE ME "POTAT-ERS"?
POTATOES.
THAT WAS SOME OF
THE TEXAS COMING OUT.
REALLY?
YEP, I CAN SEE
THE TRANSFORMATION.
YEAH, I LIVE HERE
FOR 16 YEARS.
YEAH, IT'S ALL RIGHT,
YOU GAVE ME "POTAT-ER."
THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE DOING HERE.
IT'S THE POTATO PANCAKES
STUFFED WITH THE VERY
THIN LAYER OF GROUND MEAT.
WE'RE DOING BEEF AND CHICKEN,
50-50.
WE GRIND THE BEEF,
THEN THE CHICKEN,
THEN THE ONIONS.
SAUSAGE IS READY.
SALT AND PEPPER TO THIS.
MIX IT UP.
RIGHT.
GOT IT, OKAY.
NOW WE'RE DOING
POTATOES.
WE GRIND IT HERE.
SOME ONIONS FIRST.
RAW POTATO. JUST SOAKED
IN WATER SO THEY--
JUST SOAKED IN WATER, YEAH.
SO THAT'S READY.
OKAY, I HAVE AN EGG HERE.
OKAY.
FLOUR, SALT,
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
VEGETA.
THE VEGETABLE STOCK.
YES.
OKAY, OIL'S HOT.
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT
THIS IN THERE,
EGG'S WORKING AS A BINDER,
FLOUR'S WORKING AS A BINDER.
NOW WE PUT THE MEAT DOWN.
I COVER.
AS MUCH AS YOU CAN.
SO THE POTATO, AS IT COOKS,
IS GONNA SOAK UP THE FAT
OF THE GROUND BEEF.
YOU HAVE THE BEEF FLAVOR, BUT
YOU CUT IT WITH THE CHICKEN.
OKAY, SO WHEN THEY START
TO BROWN A LITTLE BIT,
THEN WE'LL FLIP 'EM.
YES.
LOOK AT THAT.
SEE HOW BEAUTIFUL
THEY ARE?
THEY ARE GORGEOUS.
I SHOULD COVER IT.
SO WE'VE GOT THE NICE
CRISP GOING THERE,
BUT NOW WE REALLY NEED
TO INTENSIFY THE HEAT...
YES.
TO MAKE SURE WE COOK THAT
MEAT ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
YES, YES.
TEN MINUTES
IT STAYS COVERED.
OKAY, IT'S READY.
WE PUT IT ON THE PLATE.
HERE YOU ARE.
YOU GOT THE CREAMINESS
OF MASHED POTATOES,
BUT THEN YOU GET THE CRISPINESS
OF, LIKE, A LATKE.
THEN YOU GET
THE SAUSAGE INSIDE.
IT'S NOT OVER SEASONED
BY ANY MEANS.
CRISPY, CREAMY, SALTY,
WITH SOME MEAT.
RUSSIAN COMFORT FOOD.
THAT'S DYNAMITE.
THE ONLY PLACE IN DALLAS
TO FIND RUSSIAN FOOD
ARE AT MY MOTHER'S HOUSE
AND HERE,
AND MY MOTHER DOESN'T COOK,
SO WE COME HERE.
I LIKE A LOT OF THIS FOOD.
I LIKE THE FOOD THAT--
IT TAKES TIME.
IT'S NOT QUICK, INSTANTANEOUS.
IT'S LOW AND SLOW COOKING.
YOU NEED
TO STAY HERE.
YEAH, IF I STAYED HERE,
I'D BE WORKING BEHIND
OVER THERE WITH THE DOLLS,
GO IN THE ONE DOLL, IN THE
OTHER DOLL, IN THE OTHER DOLL.
UP NEXT...
WOW.
WE'RE HEADED
TO LAS VEGAS, NEVADA...
IS EVERYTHING HERE
TOASTED?
FOR TACOS AS CRAZY...
THIS IS WAY MORE
THAN A TACO.
AS THE DUDE PUTTING 'EM
TOGETHER.
NEVER HAVE I EVER SEEN
ANYBODY DEEP-FRY THE BREAD.
SO HERE I AM
IN LAS VEGAS, NEVADA,
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET FROM
MY OLD ALMA MATER U.N.L.V.
NOW WHEN I WENT TO SCHOOL HERE,
IN THIS AREA,
JUST A COUPLE OF LITTLE
FAST-FOOD JOINTS.
I COME BACK FOR A LITTLE TRIPLE
"D" VISIT, WHAT DO I FIND?
UH-HUH, FUNKY JOINTS LIKE THIS--
YAYO TACO.
(gong crashes)
IT'S PHENOMENAL.
POLLO TACO HERE.
NEVER REALLY SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT BEFORE.
ONE OF A KIND,
JUST LIKE THE
SURFER-TURNED-TACO MASTER
CHO YIU.
LOOK AT THE LID.
I'M IMPRESSED.
AND NOT JUST BECAUSE
OF THE ROCKIN' HAIRDO...
I GRADUATED AS
AN ARCHITECT AT U.S.C.
I WAS DOING ARCHITECTURE,
AND THAT KIND OF AFFORDED ME
THE OPPORTUNITY
TO DO THE TRAVELING.
AND IN 2006,
HE GAVE UP BEACH SAND
FOR DESERT SAND
AND OPENED THIS JOINT.
YAYO TACO IS BASICALLY
A PERSONAL EXPRESSION
OF THE DIFFERENT
PLACES I'VE BEEN.
BOMBAY READY.
TOTALLY DIFFERENT VARIETY
TO A NORMAL TACO.
SHANGHAI TACO HERE.
BUT WE'RE NOT TALKIN' JUST
CARNITAS AND CARNE ASADA
AND AL PASTOR, WE'RE TALKING
THE FUNKY CHICKEN.
POLLO TACO PLATE READY.
CAST OF CHARACTERS
YOU GOT IN HERE, MAN.
THIS IS THE CLASSIC
MOLE SAUCE FOR THE POLLO TACO.
OKAY.
BLACK PEPPER, OREGANO.
SERRANO CHILIES,
DEEP-FRIED.
DEEP-FRY 'EM--
GET A LITTLE BITE OUT.
GIVES YOU
A DEEPER FLAVOR.
TOASTED PUMPKIN SEEDS,
RAISINS, TOASTED,
GET IT TO CARAMELIZE
A LITTLE BIT.
BLACKENED WHITE SESAME SEEDS,
ALSO TOASTED.
TOASTED.
IS EVERYTHING HERE
TOASTED?
UH, FOR OUR MOLE SAUCE,
YEAH.
CINNAMON, CUMIN.
YES.
THYME, CLOVES--CRUSHED,
OF COURSE--
PEANUTS, TOASTED.
ALMONDS--
TOASTED
AND ALMOST BURNT.
THE THING WITH MOLES IS THAT
YOU HAVE TO REACH A STAGE
WITH ALL THE TOASTING
TO ALMOST BURNT OR BURNT.
CHIPOTLE CHILIES.
WOW, THIS IS WHERE
IT GETS FUN.
ANCHOS.
YOU KNOW,
AT LEAST FOUR CHILIES,
PRETTY MUCH DEFINES
A CLASSIC MOLE.
THIS MOLE
IS A MOLE.
GUAJILLO CHILIES.
MY FAVORITE.
HYDRATED.
WE ARE JUST GONNA PACK
THE NINJA FULL, AREN'T WE?
THE PASILLA CHILIES,
FRIED ONIONS.
AND FINALLY,
SOME TYPE OF LIQUID,
OTHERWISE WE'RE NOT
GONNA GET THE 700 POUNDS
OF BIRD SEED DOWN THERE TO MIX
UP. THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
LIQUEFY IT A LITTLE BIT,
SO IT'S A LITTLE EASIER TO BLEND
THE REST OF THE INGREDIENTS,
ESPECIALLY THE BREAD.
WHAT?
YOU DEEP-FRIED
THE BREAD?
DEEP-FRIED BREAD.
NEVER HAVE I EVER SEEN
ANYBODY DEEP-FRY THE BREAD
FOR THE MOLE,
OR FOR ANYTHING,
FOR THAT MATTER.
UH, SHOULD WE
CHALLENGE THE MACHINE?
YUP.
DEEP-FRIED GARLIC, RED TOMATO,
AND THE TOMATILLO,
WHICH ARE BOTH FRIED.
VEGETABLE STOCK,
DARK MEXICAN CHOCOLATE.
WE HAVE TO HEAT IT UP
FOR ABOUT HALF AN HOUR.
LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT
WE'RE GONNA MAKE.
A GRILL SHAKE--
WHAT WE RUB OUR MEATS WITH.
OKAY.
WE HAVE GARLIC POWDER HERE...
KOSHER SALT.
UH, IT'S LIKE A--
CHILI POWDER.
YEAH, IT COULD BE
CHILI POWDER...
CAYENNE
OR PAPRIKA.
LET'S GO WITH
CHILI POWDER.
OKAY, THIS LOOKS
LIKE CUMIN.
I'M WITH YA. JUST SHOUT IT OUT,
IF YOU KNOW THE ANSWER.
ONION POWDER.
THIS IS PAPRIKA.
CAYENNE AND OREGANO.
THYME OR--
OH, THAT IS THYME.
(whistles)
THANK YOU.
JUST MIX THIS UP.
WE'RE DONE.
OKAY, CHICKEN.
WE'RE GONNA SCORE IT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH SOME OF THE DRY RUB.
YES.
OKAY, SO WE GO WITH THIS
TO THE OVEN,
TWO, TWO AND A HALF HOURS
AT 350, COOL IT DOWN.
SOME OF THE SKIN WILL STAY,
AND THE SKIN WITH
THE FAT WILL GO.
IF IT'S JUST REGULAR
OL' COOKED-DOWN SKIN.
OH, I LOVE THAT PART.
NICE DRY RUB.
PULL THE MEAT,
AND THEN NEXT WE GET IT DRUNK.
YES.
YEAH. OKAY.
FIRST SOME WATER.
THIS IS MINT.
GINGER, STAR OF ANISE,
PULVERIZED,
CINNAMON, OOLONG TEA.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL THIS.
THERE'S NO BOOZE IN IT?
YES.
SO WHEN WE POUR THAT
OVER THE CHICKEN,
THAT'S WHEN IT GETS DRUNK--
WE ADD THE BOOZE THEN?
YES.
WAITING FOREVER TO GET
A DRINK OUT OF THIS PLACE.
WHISKEY.
THIS MARINADE HAS TO BE ABSORBED
INTO THE FLESH OVERNIGHT...
OKAY.
AND COOLED.
WE'RE ADDING THE CLASSIC
MOLE SAUCE.
NOW IT'S AT
ITS DEEPEST STATE.
STIR IT UP, AND NOW IT'S
READY TO COOK FOR SERVICE.
YES.
OKAY.
WE JUST TOASTED
SOME TACO SHELLS.
WE LIKE IT, UH,
A LITTLE TOASTY.
AND POLLO
WITH THE MOLE SAUCE.
A LITTLE ACID.
A LITTLE
TOMATILLO SALSA.
YES. POLLO TACO.
WOW.
MMM.
DUDE.
THAT'S NOT A REGULAR TACO.
THE RICHNESS AND THE FLAVOR
AND THE DEPTH
AND THE COMPLEXITY.
MMM.
I'M IMPRESSED.
NICE JOB.
(gong crashes)
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
ORIGINALLY, CHINA.
AND HE'S GOT THE TACO
TO PROVE IT...
SHANGHAI TACO PLATE.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
THIS IS WAY MORE
THAN A TACO.
CRAZY, BUT AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
IN LAS VEGAS, WHEN
A SURF-LOVING ARCHITECT
TRADES IN HIS DRAFTING BOARD
FOR A SANDWICH BOARD,
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU GET--
YAYO TACO.
A LITTLE COLLEGE TACO BEER JOINT
ACROSS THE STREET FROM U.N.L.V.
AND THE FOOD'S
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
THAN ANY OTHER PLACE
AROUND CAMPUS.
I MEAN, YOU GOT, LIKE, REAL
FOOD, CULTURALLY MADE FOOD.
SHANGHAI TACO HERE.
HAS A WONDERFUL SMOKY FLAVOR
TO IT, ADD A LITTLE HEAT,
KINDA BRINGS OUT
THE REST OF THE FLAVORS.
WE'RE CUTTING THE BEEF
FOR THE SHANGHAI TACO.
(whistles) DUDE,
THAT IS HUMUNGOUS.
THIS IS A BEEF CHUCK ROLL. WE'RE
GONNA TAKE THE LEATHER OFF.
THE LEATHER.
TRIM, LIKE,
THE BULKY FAT OUT,
BUT WE'RE GONNA LEAVE A LITTLE
BIT OF THE FAT. WE WANT--
'CAUSE WE WANT
SOME OF THE FLAVOR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA CUT IT
INTO CHUNKS OF, UH,
NOT MORE THAN, SAY,
4 OR 5 INCHES.
JUST SO IT CAN
ROAST DOWN NICE.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SEASON THIS WITH?
GRILL SHAKE.
HIT 'EM WITH THE SHAKE.
SO WE'RE GONNA
ATTEMPT THIS,
BUT WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME, UH,
VINEGAR--SOME WHITE VINEGAR.
KEEP IT MOIST AND--
TO JUST BLOOM IN THE AIR.
I LIKE THE FIST CUP.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
IS ENOUGH.
THE LOOSE TENT
IS GOOD ENOUGH.
JUST WANT TO RETAIN
SOME OF THE MOISTURE.
AND WE'RE READY FOR THE OVEN.
350?
350, 3 HOURS.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW WE'VE
GOT THE ROASTED MEAT.
CUT IT DOWN INTO
THE SLICES AND CHUNKS.
RIGHT.
SEAR IT OFF.
SEAR IT UP.
PUT SOME MORE TEXTURE TO
THE OUTSIDE OF IT, ALL RIGHT.
THE PARTS THAT SHRED
ARE GONNA CONTAIN THE SAUCES.
HERE'S THE BEEF.
CRUSHED BLACK BEAN SAUCE.
WASABI SAUCE.
VEGETABLE STOCK.
WHY IS YOUR VEGETABLE
STOCK PINK?
IT'S OUR HOUSE, UH,
VEGETABLE STOCK.
WE ADD SOME RED CABBAGE
TO IT.
OH, 'CAUSE IT LOOKED LIKE
DISH SOAP FOR A SECOND.
THAT'LL CLEAN YOU OUT.
STIR THAT,
PUT SOME HEAT IN IT.
THIS IS GONNA COOK DOWN
FOR, UM, ABOUT THREE HOURS,
LID OFF.
TO EVAPORATE, OKAY.
AT THAT TIME, WE'LL BE ADDING
SHREDDED SALTED RADISH.
AND TOFU?
TOFU.
LET IT ALL COOK DOWN, EVAPORATE
OFF A BUNCH OF THE LIQUID,
TIGHTENS UP.
WE STORE IT
OVERNIGHT,
SO IT MARINADES
WITH THE SAUCE.
THEN SCOOP IT OUT
AND HIT IT ON THE FLAT TOP.
YES.
TOFU AND THE TRIPLE
THREAT MEAT.
MAN, YOU LOAD IT
FULL OF MEAT.
THIS IS A HOUSE SLAW.
GETTIN' SAVAGE
WITH THE CABBAGE.
AND THIS IS A TSUNAMI SAUCE.
IT'S A WASABI SOUR CREAM.
WHERE'S THE BROWN
COME FROM?
THE WASABI.
MUST BE TOASTED
FOR DEEP FLAVOR.
IT IS RICH.
I THINK ONE OF THE FLAVORS THAT
IS PROBABLY THE UNDERLYING THEME
IS THAT BLACK BEAN PASTE,
AND I LOVE IT.
WHEN YOU EAT THIS,
YOU DON'T EAT IT
JUST, LIKE, TO GET IT DOWN
AND GET THROUGH IT--
YOU EAT IT, AND YOU TAKE
A BITE AND SAVOR IT
AND YOU THINK ABOUT IT
AND YOU--
THIS IS WAY MORE
THAN A TACO.
MMM.
WHERE WERE YOU
WHEN I WENT TO SCHOOL?
I MEAN, THIS--
I WOULDN'T HAVE LEFT.
YOU'VE GOT SOMETHING
GOING ON HERE.
YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF A DEEPER ISSUE GOING ON,
YOU KNOW, AND I DON'T KNOW THAT
COUNSELING'S REALLY GONNA WORK.
THIS IS YAYO TACO,
AND THAT'S HOW THEY DO IT.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE'VE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪ CHICKEN BASE
AND A GARLIC SAUCE ♪
♪ AND A JERK SAUCE ♪
YEAH!
(shouting)
YEAH, WE'RE WEIRD,
MAN.