I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
ARE YOU READY?
I AM READY!
WE'RE BELLYING UP
TO THE COUNTER...
TWO TO GO.
FOR SOME OF THIS...
(both) MODERN MIDWESTERN
COMFORT FOOD.
AND A WHOLE LOT OF THAT...
I COULD SERIOUSLY GO
TO FOOD COMA-TOWN ON THIS.
IN UPTOWN CHICAGO.
WOW, YOU'RE
GOING BIG.
A RENOVATED DIVE BAR...
NOT SOMETHING
YOU HEAR EVERY DAY.
NO.
WITH A HEAVY HAND FOR BRISKET
AND FOR SAYING
AHEAD OF THE CURVE.
STARTING TO LOOK
A LOT LIKE HEADCHEESE.
AND IN AUSTIN, TEXAS...
HOW CAN WE DO ANY
MORE TO ANYTHING?
A FRONT-ROW SEAT...
WHOA!
FOR A COUPLE
PUTTING ON A SHOW...
YOU GET TWO
WITH AN ORDER?
WITH A SPIN ON DOWN-HOME
COMFORT FOOD.
I WISH I COULD GET TOOTHPASTE
THAT TASTED LIKE THIS.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D"
I SAY IT ALL THE TIME--
IF IT'S FUNKY, I'LL FIND IT,
BUT WHAT DOES FUNKY MEAN?
I MEAN, FUNKY'S A GOOD THING.
FUNKY'S DIFFERENT.
FUNKY'S UNIQUE.
FUNKY IS OFF THE HOOK.
THAT COULD BE THE PEOPLE,
IT COULD BE THE PLACE,
IT COULD BE THE STORY,
OR IN THIS CASE IT'S THE MENU.
I'M HERE IN ANDERSONVILLE, ABOUT
6 MILES FROM DOWNTOWN CHICAGO,
TO CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS HOPLEAF BAR.
I GOT A STEW AND A TILAPIA
GOING TO 209.
EXTRAORDINARY WHEN
IT COMES TO PUB FOOD.
YOU'RE NOT QUITE EXPECTING
WHAT GETS PUT IN FRONT OF YOU.
THE CHARCUTERIE TRIO--
HEADCHEESE, RABBIT RILLETTE,
AND DUCK PROSCIUTTO.
IT HAS TO BE
BEER-FRIENDLY.
THAT'S THE WHOLE
IDEA.
YEP.
MIKE'S A BIG PART OF IT.
I MEAN, HE BUILT THIS.
HE'S ALWAYS HERE.
AND IT'S BEEN 20 YEARS
IN THE MAKING.
I BOUGHT IT IN 1992.
BACK WHEN IT WAS A TOTAL DIVE.
LIKE AN OLD, SWEDISH,
OLD-MAN BAR.
BUT MICHAEL ROPER
HAD OTHER IDEAS.
PUT THE KITCHEN IN
ABOUT 12 YEARS AGO.
THAT INCLUDED
CHEF BEN SHEAGREN.
MUSSEL FOR TWO, BEER.
AND IMMEDIATELY
HUGE, HUGE HIT.
THEY ALWAYS FIND A DIFFERENT WAY
TO PAIR SOMETHING WITH THE BEER.
THE BRISKET SANDWICH
ON SOURDOUGH.
(man) I LOVE ORDERING
THE BRISKET
EVERY TIME I COME HERE.
(Ben) THIS IS THE MONTREAL
SMOKED BEEF BRISKET SANDWICH.
AND WHAT ARE WE
GONNA DO WITH THIS?
WE ARE GOING
TO MAKE OUR RUB
STARTING WITH
KOSHER SALT,
BLACK PEPPER,
SMOKED SWEET PAPRIKA,
LIGHT BROWN SUGAR,
GROUND CUMIN, GROUND FENNEL...
(whistles)
GROUND CORIANDER...
WOW, YOU'RE GOING BIG.
GROUND CELERY SEED,
GROUND MUSTARD SEED,
MUSTARD POWDER,
ALLSPICE, PINK SALT.
THIS IS A FAIRLY TYPICAL
MONTREAL-STYLE RUB.
THIS IS ORGANIC,
GRASS-FED BRISKET.
THIS IS MINCED GARLIC.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
OF A GARLIC MASSAGE, MAKE SURE
THAT IT MAKES THE RIGHT CONTACT
WITH THE MEAT,
BUT IT ALSO DOES CREATE
KIND OF AN ADHESIVE LAYER
FOR THE RUB TO CLING TO.
"ADHESIVE LAYER"--
NOT SOMETHING
YOU HEAR EVERY DAY.
NO.
LIKE SO, AND IT'S
A GENEROUS LAYER.
BOTH SIDES.
NICELY DONE.
YOU GONNA LET THIS SIT HERE
AND MARINATE FOR A DAY,
OR WHAT--
THIS IS GONNA BE IN
THE COOLER FOR 72 HOURS.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THREE DAYS.
TRANSFER IT
TO THE SHEET TRAY.
SO YOU'RE GONNA
HIT IT WITH THE BACON.
RED WINE ON THE BOTTOM--
STAYS NICE AND MOIST AND JUICY.
AND GO INTO
THE SMOKER WITH IT.
TYPE OF WOOD?
WE USE APPLE.
8 HOURS, 250.
ALL THAT WORK AND LOVE
TO THAT LITTLE BRISKET.
LEAVE A LITTLE
OF THAT FAT CAP ON THERE.
YEAH.
PAUL BUNYAN
COMING OVER FOR LUNCH?
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE
WITH THAT?
THIS IS ABOUT
THE SERVING SIZE.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
THE WAY IT'S
GONNA BE SERVED?
ON SOURDOUGH
WHICH IS TOASTED
AND SLATHERED
WITH GRAINY MUSTARD.
SLATHERED.
THAT'S REALLY NOT
HOW MUCH MEAT YOU PUT ON IT.
OH, YEAH.
♪♪♪
IS THAT A SIDE OF FOOD LUBE
YOU PUT ON THERE?
THAT'S AIOLI.
THE FRIES ARE GANGSTER.
THOSE ARE HAND-CUT
EVERY DAY.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS--
HALF THE SANDWICH HANGS
OUT THE BACK OF THE BREAD.
(laughing)
OH, THAT'S RIDICULOUS--
TENDER BUT JUICY,
FALL-APART, VERY UNCTUOUS.
IT'S A PACKAGE
DEAL, MAN.
FOR NOT BEING
A BARBECUE JOINT,
IT'S ONE OF THE MORE
LEGIT BRISKETS I'VE HAD.
THIS IS AWESOME.
TWO TO GO.
THANK YOU.
BRISKET ON SOURDOUGH
TO 202.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THE BEST BRISKET THAT I'VE HAD.
(man) THEY HAVE INCREDIBLE
RELATIONSHIPS
WITH LOCAL FARMERS. ALMOST BE
BLASPHEMY FOR THEM TO NOT USE
EVERY SINGLE PART
OF THE ANIMALS THAT THEY GET.
AND THEY DO MEAN EVERY PART.
OH, THIS'LL BE ON
THE FRONT PAGE OF MY BOOK.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
TODAY I MIGHT HAVE PUSHED
MYSELF TO ANOTHER BOUNDARY.
WE'RE MAKING HEADCHEESE.
AWESOME SAUSAGE.
IT'S AWESOME SAUSAGE.
YEAH. YEAH.
THERE YOU GO.
SO WELCOME BACK
TO TRIPLE "D."
SO WE'RE AT ANDERSONVILLE
IN CHICAGO,
HANGING OUT AT HOPLEAF.
AND BOY,
DO WE HAVE A SURPRISE.
WE'RE MAKING HEADCHEESE.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN HERE.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR PIG'S HEAD.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT INTIMIDATING
FOR PEOPLE.
NO. WHY?
WE START WITH HOT WATER
AND SOME PINK SALT
FOR PRESERVATION,
SUGAR, AND SOME KOSHER SALT.
A TRADITIONAL BRINE.
THIS IS VERY WELL ACCEPTED
IN MANY CULTURES.
YEAH.
WASTE NOT, WANT NOT.
ABSOLUTELY.
THE BEST PARTS
OF THE ANIMAL
ARE FREQUENTLY FOUND
ON THE HEAD.
THE CHEEK OF JUST ABOUT
ANYTHING IS THE BEST EATING.
MMM.
THAT CHEEK MEAT IS SOME
OF THE MOST FLAVORFUL
IN ALL OF THE SWINE.
MIX THIS BRINE UP
A LITTLE BIT.
I HOPE YOU
APPRECIATE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME COLD WATER.
SNOUT DOWN,
LIFT BY THE EARS.
WHOO-HOO!
AND...
HOW LONG WILL IT BRINE?
THIS WILL BRINE
FOR TWO DAYS.
ALL RIGHT, YOU READY
FOR THIS?
YEP.
ALWAYS BY THE EARS.
AND THEY DON'T TEAR OFF?
NO, THEY ARE TOUGH.
OH, THIS WILL BE
ON THE FRONT PAGE OF MY BOOK.
WE GO INTO THE POT.
WE ARE GOING TO BUILD
A STOCK, ESSENTIALLY,
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE HAM HOCKS,
ONIONS, CARROTS,
CELERY, LEEKS.
WE'RE STARTING
TO GET PRETTY FULL.
STARTING TO GET
A LITTLE FULL?
AND THEN WE'VE GOT
SOME THYME, PARSLEY...
THYME AND LOOKS
LIKE PARSLEY.
BAY LEAF,
AND PEPPERCORN.
THIS IS GONNA SIMMER
OVERNIGHT.
OKAY, SO WE LET THIS GO
10 TO 12 HOURS.
IT'S READY TO COME OUT.
YOU READY?
BASICALLY DO
THE SALAD TONG APPROACH HERE.
(grunts)
YOU GOT ALL THAT?
MM-HMM.
LIKE I WAS GONNA JUMP IN
AND HELP.
(chuckles)
THOSE HOCKS HAVE JUST TURNED
INTO JELLY, PRACTICALLY.
THERE'S SOME EXCELLENT MEAT
AS WELL.
MMM.
I'M EXCITED TO TRY IT.
IT'LL BE GOOD.
SO WE GOT A GOOD CHEEK
ON THIS SIDE.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
PICK THROUGH,
GET THE PIECES
THAT LOOK GOOD.
OH, HIS TONGUE'S
IN THERE.
YOU CAN SEE. OH, YES.
(whistles)
THIS IS ONE
OF THE BETTER EXAMPLES.
THERE WE GO.
THAT'S WHERE THE CHRISTMAS GIFT
WAS--RIGHT DOWNTOWN.
THIS IS THE CHEEK,
UNSEASONED?
GOOD EXAMPLE--
THAT IS THE CHEEK.
MMM.
SO THE REDUCED LIQUID.
THIS STARTED OUT AS WHAT,
PROBABLY 4 GALLONS?
MAN, THAT IS A LOT
OF REDUCTION.
OKAY.
THIS IS YOUR DUNCE CAP,
BUT WE HAVE
TO FILL IT FIRST.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
THAT PICKED MEAT,
WE'RE JUST GONNA
SHOVE IT IN THERE.
THAT LEAVES ME
ENOUGH ROOM THERE
TO COMPACT THE MEAT
A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S STARTING TO LOOK
A LOT LIKE HEADCHEESE.
AND SO WE'VE GOT
LIQUEFIED ASPIC.
JUST KIND OF SQUEEZE IT
A LITTLE BIT,
LET IT SETTLE DOWN
INTO THE NOOKS AND CRANNIES.
THAT'S WHAT'S GONNA CONGEAL,
TIGHTEN THIS ALL UP,
AND MAKE IT INTO A SAUSAGE.
THERE YOU GO. MAGICAL.
OKAY, THAT'S GOOD.
WE'RE GOOD?
THEN WE DO
SOMETHING CALLED WHIPPING,
SO WE HAVE
A NICE UNIFORM TUBE.
WHIP IT GOOD.
LET IT GO OVERNIGHT.
IT'LL COOL DOWN,
AND WE'LL BE READY
TO ROCK 'N' ROLL.
WOW, IT IS DENSE.
THE FIRST SLICE
WILL TELL US HOW WE DID.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
PEEL OFF THAT CASING
FOR YOU THERE.
I'LL WORK ON THE SLICES.
YOU, UH...
ALL RIGHT. LOOKS
PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
YEAH. NO, IT CUTS NICE.
A LITTLE TURNIP
AND A LITTLE MUSTARD.
LOAD IT UP TO REFLECT
HOW BRAVE YOU ARE.
AWESOME.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN TASTE IT.
THE FLAVOR'S REAL.
IT'S NOT 1/100th
AS INTIMIDATING
AS I THINK PEOPLE
WOULD EXPECT.
MM-HMM.
I MEAN, YOU'VE GOT YOUR
SEASONING DOWN PAT, DUDE.
UH-HUH. YEP.
I AM SO IMPRESSED WITH THIS.
AWESOME SAUSAGE.
YEAH.
THAT'S THE BEST WAY TO DESCRIBE
IT. IT'S AWESOME SAUSAGE.
HEADCHEESE
AND RABBIT RILLETTE, 202.
(man) IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S GOT A SWEET VELVETY TASTE.
IT'S VERY DELICATE.
A LOT OF JOINTS LIKE THIS?
NO.
YOU GOT A LOT OF BEER.
YOU GOT A LOT OF ENERGY.
THERE'S A LOT GOING ON,
AND THE MENU'S LEADING THE WAY.
I GOTTA APPLAUD YOU.
GOOD CHOICE.
COOL. COOL.
UP NEXT...
A MASTERPIECE.
WE'RE HEADED
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS...
HOLY MOLY.
WHERE A COUPLE
IS ROCKIN' OUT
THE MAIN DISHES...
I GOT SOME TOOLS
OUT IN THE CAMARO
IF YOU WANT TO USE THEM
TO UNBOLT THE KITCHEN SINK.
AND ALWAYS SAVING ROOM
FOR DESSERT.
I LOVE CHEESE, SO...
OH, YOU MUST WATCH
MY SHOW.
YEAH.
♪♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN CENTRAL AUSTIN
IN AN AREA KNOWN
AS THE NORTH LOOP,
WHERE A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
WHO MET IN CULINARY SCHOOL
HAVE OPENED UP A PLACE
IN AN OLD SKATE SHOP,
SERVING UP ECLECTIC,
INTERNATIONAL COMFORT FOOD.
WOW, THAT'S A MOUTHFUL,
JUST LIKE THIS PLACE.
THIS IS FOREIGN & DOMESTIC.
WE GOT CHICKEN
AND A BRAISED BEEF.
THIS IS THE MOST UNIQUE PLACE
I'VE EVER EATEN IN AUSTIN.
THEY'RE A GENUINE
FOOD-FOCUSED PLACE.
FROM TWO POINTS OF VIEW.
(woman) NED AND JODI
ARE HUSBAND AND WIFE
AND OUR COOKING
WHAT THEY'RE PASSIONATE ABOUT.
I DO PASTRIES AND BAKING,
AND HE DOES
ALL THE ENTREES
AND APPETIZERS.
AND THEY GOT THE CHOPS
TO BACK IT UP.
JODI WAS A PASTRY CHEF
IN LONDON,
AND NED DID HIS TIME
IN NEW YORK CITY KITCHENS.
IN 2010, THEY BROUGHT
THOSE EXPERIENCES TO AUSTIN.
FOREIGN TECHNIQUE APPLIED
TO KIND OF DOMESTIC DISHES.
INTERNATIONAL FOOD
BUT COMFORT FOOD.
WE'VE GOT A FIDEO
AND A SOUP.
THIS IS CALLED FIDEO.
IT'S PASTA THAT'S BEEN SAUTéED
FIRST AND THEN COOKED IN BROTH.
FIDEOS MEANS...
THE ODDS AND ENDS
OF THE ANGEL HAIR PASTA.
FIDEOS WITH WHAT?
MUSSELS AND CLAMS,
SOME BACON.
BACON'S TASTY. WHERE'S THAT
FROM? DON'T SAY THE PIGS.
WE MAKE THAT IN HOUSE.
YOU MAKE THE BACON
IN HOUSE?
YEAH. PAN HOT.
OKAY.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF THE COOKING OIL TO IT.
MUSSELS AND CLAMS. THEN WE'RE
GONNA ADD NOODLES--FIDEOS--IN.
SO WE'RE TOASTING UP
THE PASTA A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH. SORT OF LIKE
A RISOTTO.
MAKES IT MORE TOOTHSOME.
SPANISH
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
YOU BETTER HURRY UP
ON THE, UM, DISH
BEFORE I EAT
ALL THE BACON.
WHITE WINE.
WE'LL LET THAT
COOK DOWN.
BROWN CHICKEN STOCK
WE MAKE IN HOUSE.
CARAMELIZED FENNEL?
YEAH, CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
THE HOUSE CURED
AND SMOKED BACON,
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF CHOPPED...
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
AND YOU JUST GIVE IT
A NICE LITTLE STIR
AND LET THAT COME UP
TO A SIMMER.
AND THEN JUST POP IT
IN THE OVEN AND LET IT BAKE.
LET IT FINISH OFF,
ABSORB THE REST
OF THAT STOCK.
SO WE SERVE IT
WITH TOASTED BAGUETTE,
BACON FAT,
WE HAVE A GRILL PAN HERE.
YOU KNOW, MARK IT OFF
ON EACH SIDE,
NICE AND TOASTY.
NICE.
THAT'S REDUCED NICE
AND NOW IT'S TIGHTENED UP.
TAKE THE TOAST OFF, AND THEN
WE'LL FINISH UP WITH THE DISH.
SO I'M GONNA ADD SOME
OF THE BéCHAMEL TO IT,
SOME OF THE EGGPLANT BUTTER.
EGGPLANT BUTTER?
WE TAKE EGGPLANTS,
BLISTER AND CARAMELIZE THEM.
OUR GREEN TOMATO JAM
AND THEN SOME OF THE--
QUITE A DISH, MAN.
SOME OF THE PUMPKIN SEEDS,
ROASTED LIME--
WE LOVE ROASTING THINGS HERE.
STIR THAT.
READY TO GO TO THE BOWL.
IT SMELLS AWESOME.
SO WE DO A LITTLE BIT MORE.
HOW CAN WE DO ANY MORE
TO ANYTHING?
SO WE DRESS THE TOAST WITH
A LITTLE MORE GREEN TOMATO JAM,
PUMPKIN SEED OVER THE TOP,
TOAST,
A LITTLE HERB SALAD,
SOME PICKLED RED ONIONS,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
THERE IT IS.
ALL RIGHT, A MASTERPIECE.
MMM!
WOW. MMM.
SEAFOOD IS ONLY ONE
SMALL COMPONENT.
TOASTING THAT PASTA
REALLY GIVES IT SOME TOOTH.
IT'S GOT A NICE SILKINESS
TO IT.
AND THEN YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE ACID FROM THE JAM.
MY MOUTH'S EVERYWHERE.
I COULD SERIOUSLY GO
TO FOOD COMA-TOWN ON THIS.
A WHOLE ASSORTMENT OF FOOD
IN ONE BOWL.
IT'S A VIRTUAL
CORNUCOPIA.
ALL COMING TOGETHER
RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOUR EYES.
I REALLY ENJOY WATCHING NED
AND THE OTHER CHEFS COOK.
I'VE GOT
A CHANTERELLE SOUP.
I THINK IT'S FUN
TO INTERACT WITH PEOPLE.
YOU ACTUALLY FEEL INSPIRED BY
THE FOOD THAT'S DELIVERED TO YOU
BECAUSE YOU FEEL LIKE YOU GOT
TO BE A PART OF IT BEING MADE.
YOU GET EXCITED
TO TRY NEW THINGS.
(Ned) I GOT
A FRIED CHICKEN BISCUIT.
WHAT ARE YOU HAVING?
FRIED CHICKEN
WITH BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
A BRUNCH ITEM WE HAVE HERE
IS A FRIED CHICKEN BISCUIT.
WE USE CHICKEN THIGHS
FOR THIS.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE MARINADE
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTERMILK
WE MAKE IN HOUSE.
AND THE REASON TO MAKE
THE BUTTERMILK
VERSUS BUY IT?
WE LIKE
TO MAKE EVERYTHING HERE.
JODI ACTUALLY GOT IT
FROM HER GRANDMOTHER.
IF YOU CAN MAKE IT
BETTER THAN YOU CAN BUY IT,
YOU SHOULD TRY TO DO IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF HOT SAUCE,
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
GARLIC POWDER, A LITTLE BIT
OF MUSTARD POWDER.
GIVE IT A STIR AND DROP
THE THIGHS IN THERE.
LET THEM MARINATE
FOR AT LEAST 24 HOURS,
NO MORE THAN 36 HOURS.
NOW WE DREDGE IT?
YEAH.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
GARLIC POWDER,
SMOKED PAPRIKA,
AND JUST--JUST
A LITTLE BIT...
NICE COLOR
ON THAT.
PEPPER, THE BALEINE
FRENCH SEA SALT.
MIX THAT UP.
TAKE THE CHICKEN
OUT OF THE MARINADE.
CHUG SOME
OF THE BUTTERMILK?
MAYBE WE'LL HAVE
A CONTEST LATER.
THROW A LITTLE DREDGE
ON THESE.
SO WE DO THEM
AT ABOUT 350--7, 8 MINUTES.
AND SO WE COOK THEM
IN A BLEND
OF DUCK FAT, CANOLA,
AND OLIVE OIL.
OH, GOING OLD SCHOOL
WITH IT.
CAST-IRON
AND THE WHOLE GIDDYAP.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
AND WE SERVE IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF REDEYE GRAVY.
DO YOU KNOW MY MIDDLE NAME
IS REDEYE GRAVY?
THIS IS A LOT
FOR REDEYE GRAVY.
COOKING OIL,
SOME CHOPPED-UP ONIONS--
WE'RE GONNA
LET THOSE SWEAT OUT.
HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE,
AND IT'S ALL HEIRLOOM
AND HERITAGE BREEDS.
BREAK THE SAUSAGE APART.
LET THAT RENDER DOWN.
SO YOU'RE GONNA USE SOME
OF THAT FAT
TO BUILD SOME OF THE ROUX.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD IN
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
SOME FRESH THYME,
COFFEE GROUNDS,
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT
OF INSTANT ESPRESSO.
SO THE ESPRESSO
I UNDERSTAND,
BUT HOW DOES
THAT COFFEE GROUND DISSIPATE?
IT DOESN'T BREAK DOWN.
IT GIVES IT ALMOST LIKE
A TOOTHSOME--
THAT YOU HAVE
A LOT OF, LIKE, PEPPER IN IT.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME BUTTER.
WHOA!
A.P. FLOUR.
BUILD THE ROUX--
GOT IT.
SO WE LET THE ROUX
COOK OUT,
AND WE LIKE TO GET
A LIGHT BROWN.
YOU WANT TO FLIP
THAT CHICKEN, BOSS?
NOW THE ROUX'S READY
TO ADD THE MILK.
BRING THAT
BACK UP TO A SIMMER.
BREWED COFFEE.
SO IT'S GONNA HAVE
THE FLAVOR.
IT'S JUST GONNA HAVE CREAMINESS
AND SAUSAGE IN IT ALSO.
YES.
OKAY, THEN.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
TABASCO.
I'VE GOT SOME TOOLS
OUT IN THE CAMARO
IF YOU WANT TO USE THEM
TO UNBOLT THE KITCHEN SINK.
YEAH. (laughs)
THEN YOU CAN PUT THAT
IN THERE.
AND WE'LL JUST LET THAT
COME BACK UP AND COOK OUT.
SO WE HAVE THE CHICKEN BISCUIT,
READY TO PLATE IT UP.
REDEYE GRAVY,
FRIED CHICKEN THIGH,
SUNNY-SIDE UP EGG,
SOME OF THE ROMAINE SLAW.
AND THEN WE DO A LITTLE BIT
OF LEMON JAM WITH IT.
LOOK AT THAT!
MMM.
AND THE REDEYE GRAVY--
THAT'S WHAT GRAVY MISSES
ALL THE TIME
IS IT JUST DOESN'T GET
THAT--THAT LITTLE COFFEE BITE.
LOOK HOW TENDER
THE CHICKEN IS.
MMM. THAT'S
A ROCK STAR BITE RIGHT THERE.
ONLY AVAILABLE AT BRUNCH?
YEAH.
THAT'S NOT GONNA WORK.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT.
PREPARE YOURSELF FOR
BREAKFAST FRIED CHICKEN...
NIGHTS.
TO DINNER FRIED CHICKEN
AT ALL TIMES.
WE CLEAR ON THAT?
OH, YEAH. OH, YEAH.
SEE? WORKING FOR YOU.
IF YOU WANT
SOMETHING FOREIGN,
WE HAVE BLACK PEPPER
AND GRUYèRE POPOVERS
FROM JODI MY WIFE.
OH, THAT I GOTTA TRY
WHEN WE COME BACK.
TRIPLE "D" HANGING OUT
AT FOREIGN & DOMESTIC
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS.
AWESOME.
AT FOREIGN & DOMESTIC
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
NED AND JODI ELLIOTT
ARE DOING THEIR PART
TO KEEP AUSTIN WEIRD.
AUSTIN, THE ECLECTIC MELTING POT
OF PEOPLE AND MUSIC,
AND YOU CAN'T FIND A PLACE
LIKE THIS?
NOT LIKE THIS.
NO, NO.
REALLY?
THERE'S CREATIVITY.
THERE'S ALWAYS A SURPRISE.
THE DESSERTS ARE INCREDIBLE.
THAT'S JODI'S DEPARTMENT...
I DO A LOT
OF THE BAKING/PASTRY STUFF.
SHE'S JUST AN AMAZING
PASTRY CHEF--TOP NOTCH,
LIKE, BLOW ME OUT OF THE WATER.
CRANKING OUT EVERYTHING
FROM BANANA TARTS
TO CINNAMON ROLLS...
INCREDIBLE.
(Jodi) HERE'S SOME POPOVERS
FOR YOU GUYS TO SHARE.
AND THIS CLASSIC
DONE HER WAY.
WE ARE GONNA MAKE GRUYèRE
AND BLACK PEPPER
POPOVERS.
HMM.
I LOVE CHEESE. IT'S ALWAYS
GOOD TO STICK IT ONTO STUFF.
OH, YOU MUST WATCH
MY SHOW.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
SO A LITTLE CHEESE--
THANK YOU.
BE HERE ALL WEEK.
I DO.
YES. I'VE MADE
A LOT OF POPOVERS.
REALLY?
YEAH, BUT THEY NEVER
POP OVER.
THEY JUST TURN
INTO REAL BAD BISCUITS.
(laughs)
I DON'T HAVE THIS. WHAT IS THIS,
SIX LITTLE MUNCHKIN HATS?
THAT'S THE POPOVER PAN.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THAT.
OOH.
SEE, THERE'S PROBABLY
THE BEGINNING...
YEAH, YOU CAN'T
USE A MUFFIN TIN.
SEE, THAT'S MY PROBLEM.
YES.
RIGHT TOOL FOR THE JOB.
FIRST STEP--
POPOVER PAN IN THE OVEN.
IT HAS TO BE HOT
BEFORE YOU PUT THE BATTER IN.
IT'S A LITTLE SECRET.
WHOLE EGGS, SOME SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
LOTS OF IT.
YES, LOTS OF IT.
AND WE'LL WHISK THAT
TOGETHER.
YOU'RE MAKING THIS
LOOK TOO EASY ALREADY.
IT'S EASY.
I PROMISE.
WHERE IS OUR
LEAVENING AGENT?
RIGHT HERE.
YOU GET IT SUPER PUFFED
WITH THAT?
WITH JUST--
TRUST ME. PROMISE.
YOU HAVE HAVE A CAPE ON,
DO YOU?
NO.
THE SECRET IS YOU HAVE
TO HAVE THE BATTER WARM.
REALLY?
YEAH, SERIOUSLY.
IF YOU HAVE A COLD,
IT WON'T WORK.
LOOK AT THE AMOUNT OF PEPPER
IN HERE.
BIG SEASONING--WOW.
YOU WANT ME WHISKING OR...
SURE. HOT MILK.
NICE AND STEAMY.
SO WE ARE GOING TO ADD
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR
BUT ADD IT
IN THREE STAGES.
AND WE WHISK THAT UP.
SECOND BATCH OF FLOUR.
AND THIS IS JUST TO MAKE SURE
THAT YOU INCORPORATE IT
INCREDIBLY WELL AND IT'S--
RIGHT.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
LIKE PANCAKE BATTER.
PANCAKE BATTER.
RIGHT, SO YOU DON'T WANT--
DO YOU DON'T WANT
TO BREAK EVERYBODY DOWN.
EXACTLY.
OUR LAST LITTLE BIT HERE.
YOU WANT TO MIX IT JUST UNTIL
IT'S ALL INCORPORATED.
THERE CAN BE LUMPS.
THEY'LL BAKE OUT.
NOBODY WILL KNOW.
ALL RIGHT. MOVE THIS OVER.
I USE A LITTLE
HANDY DANDY PITCHER.
WE TAKE THE POPOVER PAN
OUT OF THE OVEN.
IT'S VERY HOT,
SO BE VERY, VERY, VERY CAREFUL.
WE'RE GONNA SPRAY IT
JUST A SMIDGE.
YOU'RE MUCH MORE LIBERAL
WITH IT THAN I AM.
THE TRICK IS TO FILL IT
ALL THE WAY TO THE TOP.
YOU CAN BE AFRAID OF--
NONE OF THIS HALFWAY STUFF,
'CAUSE OTHERWISE...
RIDICULOUSNESS.
THEY WON'T POP OVER.
WHEN ARE WE
GONNA CHEESE IT?
RIGHT NOW.
THEN WE HAVE THE--JUST CUBES
OF GRUYèRE.
OH, HO HO.
GENEROUS--
THE MORE CHEESE, THE BETTER.
ALL RIGHT.
AND HOW LONG
ARE THESE GONNA COOK OFF?
THEY TAKE ABOUT 45 MINUTES
TO AN HOUR
IN ABOUT A 350-
OR 375-DEGREE OVEN.
UNLESS I CAN'T WAIT
FOR IT.
I'LL GUARD THE OVEN.
OKAY.
OKEYDOKEY.
OKAY, YOU READY?
I AM READY.
WAIT TILL YOU SEE THIS. OHH!
AND VOILà--
POPOVERS.
SEE, AND THEY LIVE UP
TO THE NAME, YEAH?
NO.
I'M GONNA PUT
TWO RIGHT HERE,
AND JUST IN CASE
YOU DIDN'T GET ENOUGH CHEESE,
JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE
JUST TO MAKE IT PRETTY.
YOU GET TWO
WITH AN ORDER?
YES. WE DON'T
MESS AROUND HERE.
CHEESY, SALTY GOODNESS--
LOOK AT THAT.
(chuckles)
AND IT'S JUST NICE AND LIGHT
AND AIRY. LOOK AT THAT.
(crunches)
MMM. OH, MY GOSH.
WHEN IT'S DONE THE RIGHT WAY,
IT'S RICH AND LIGHT
AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S LIKE A GRILLED CHEESE
GONE WILD.
LIKE AN EXPLOSION
AT THE GRILLED CHEESE FACTORY.
OHH!
I WISH I COULD GET TOOTHPASTE
THAT TASTED LIKE THIS.
(laughs)
THAT'S NUTS.
THIS SCREAMS FOR TOMATO SOUP
AND SOME MAYBERRY RERUNS.
THIS TOOK ME
TO MY COMFORT PLACE.
THAT'S AWESOME. MMM.
THEY'RE OUTSTANDING.
YOU ROCK.
THANK YOU.
MMM! HOLY MOLY.
THANK YOU. (laughs)
THEY'RE FREAKIN' AWESOME.
(laughs)
THEY'RE RIDICULOUS.
AND YOU CAN'T GET IT
ANYWHERE ELSE.
PRETTY MUCH HOME RUNS
ACROSS THE BOARD?
DEFINITELY. ALL 10s.
I LIKE IT.
(Guy) THE NAME FITS--
FOREIGN & DOMESTIC.
TAKING FOREIGN ITEMS--
MAKING THEM DOMESTIC.
COOKING DOMESTIC ITEMS--MAKING
THEM A LITTLE BIT FOREIGN.
(Jodi) MM-HMM.
HANDMADE, SCRATCH-MADE FOOD
STRAIGHT OUT OF THE KITCHEN
RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
WHAT YOU SEE
IS WHAT YOU GET.
AND YOU GUYS
ARE THE REAL DEAL.
WHEN YOU'RE IN AUSTIN, YOU GOT
TO CHECK THIS JOINT OUT.
AND DON'T FORGET
WHO BROUGHT YOU--TRIPLE "D."
SEE YOU NEXT WEEK. MMM!
(chuckles)
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR-TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
HAVE YOU BEEN
TO BELGIUM?
I HAVE,
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
YOU REMEMBER
MOST OF IT?
FLYING IN, FLYING OUT.
SO THE KEY POINTS.
THE KEY POINTS.
ALL RIGHT. (laughs)