HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I'M GONNA END UP
STICKING TO SOMETHING.
I'M SAMPLING THE WORLD...
MOST PEOPLE HAVE NOT HEARD
OF THIS TYPE OF FOOD
OR EVEN TRIED IT.
BY STAYING STATESIDE...
DO YOU HEAR
WHAT I'M SAYIN'?
IN NEW YORK CITY.
(mouths words)
THE DRUZE RESTAURANT--
YEAH, LOOK IT UP--
CREATING THEIR OWN SPIN...
LIKE, "NEW YORK TIMES" THIN.
ON MIDDLE EASTERN
COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S LIKE A CROSS BETWEEN
WRESTLING A SNAKE
AND MAKING TAFFY.
IN LAS VEGAS, NEVADA...
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
THE ASIAN FUSION
BURGER JOINT...
YOU SHOULD HAVE
A GRIN LIKE THAT.
PUTTING LOADS OF FLAVOR
IN EVERY FLIP.
AND IN RICHARDSON, TEXAS,
THE LEBANESE SPOT
THAT'S TRIPPING OFF...
(sirens wailing)
THE FLAVOR TOWN ALARM.
SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA.
I HAVE TO COME HERE AT LEAST
ONCE A WEEK, OR I'LL DIE.
DIE?
YEAH, I'LL JUST
STRAIGHT-UP DIE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN NEW YORK CITY
DOING WHAT EVERYBODY
IN NEW YORK CITY DOES--WALK.
I'M TAKING YOU TO A JOINT--
NOW CHECK THIS OUT.
MOST PEOPLE HAVE NOT
HEARD OF THIS TYPE OF FOOD
OR EVEN TRIED IT.
IT'S A MIDDLE EASTERN ETHNICITY
AND RELIGION KNOWN AS DRUZE,
AND THE JOIN THAT'S
SERVING THIS FOOD UP
IS RIGHT HERE--GAZALA PLACE.
FISH BOUREKAS,
TABLE ONE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE AFRAID
TO TRY SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
IT'S DRUZE, AND IT'S ALL
THROUGHOUT THE MIDDLE EAST.
IT SENT ME HOME LOOKING UP
ON THE INTERNET,
"WHAT IS--
WHAT IS DRUZE?"
GAZALA HALABI DOESN'T HAVE
TO LOOK IT UP. SHE LIVES IT.
YOU REALLY CAME
FROM A VILLAGE?
MM-HMM.
THERE IS NO WAY FOR A DRUZE
WOMAN TO COME HERE BY HERSELF,
UNLESS WITH PARENTS,
WITH HUSBAND.
THAT'S JUST WHAT SHE AND HER
HUSBAND DID TEN YEARS AGO.
COME TO AMERICA TO OPEN
A BUSINESS, TO BE SUCCESS.
SHE'S AMAZING.
GAZALA'S TOUCH IS IN
EVERY PART OF THIS JOINT.
FROM THE CHANDELIERS
THAT SHE MADE
TO THE SEWING IN THE CUSHIONS.
SO YOU PUT
THE KITCHEN IN.
YEAH.
THIS,
WITHOUT QUESTION,
IS THE SMALLEST KITCHEN
WE'VE EVER DONE IN TRIPE "D."
PRISON CELLS
ARE BIGGER THAN THIS.
BUT IT'S BIG ENOUGH TO SERVE
THE FOOD SHE GREW UP WITH...
(Gazala) LAMB'S ALMOST READY.
HER CULTURE'S TAKE ON POPULAR
MIDDLE EASTERN FOOD.
BOUREKAS, TABLE TEN.
IS A LOT OF YOUR FOOD
VEGETARIAN?
A LOT OF VEGETARIAN
DISHES, YES.
LIKE THIS EVERYDAY CLASSIC.
THE PITA HERE
IS TOTALLY DIFFERENT
THAN ANYTHING YOU'VE HAD
ANYWHERE ELSE.
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE PITA.
OKAY.
WE PUT THE WHOLE
FLOUR.
WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR.
ALL-PURPOSE?
MM-HMM.
SUGAR, SALT,
NOW WE MIX IT.
WHAT'S THIS PART,
THOUGH?
IT'S, LIKE, TO MAKE IT
MORE SOFT ALL TOGETHER.
NOW WATER.
I'M GONNA NEED
MORE WATER.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO GET IT?
YEAH, PLEASE.
DO I--DO YOU WANT ME
TO JUST CLIMB OVER, OR...
YOU HAVE TO LEARN HOW
TO PASS IN THIS KITCHEN.
(laughing)
I'M GONNA END UP
STICKING TO SOMETHING.
(laughing)
THAT WAS EASY.
YOU'RE REALLY
GIVING THIS A WORKOUT.
IS IT SUPPOSED TO BE
TACKY LIKE THAT, WET?
IT HAS
TO BE WET.
IT'S LIKE A CROSS BETWEEN
WRESTLING A SNAKE
AND MAKING TAFFY.
OKAY, IT'S READY.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WE'RE GONNA WAIT
20 MINUTES.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT--
WHAT IS THE PITA MACHINE.
THERE'S
A PITA MACHINE?
WHAT'S IT
CALLED? SAJ.
NO, I'M ASKING.
I DIDN'T KNOW THERE'S SUCH
THING AS A PITA MACHINE.
AH.
WE CALL IT
BACK HOME SAJ.
PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
WHAT SAJ IS.
OKAY.
THEY THING
"MASSAGE..."
OKAY.
AND IF YOU HAVE
ONE OF THOSE MACHINES,
YOU SHOULDN'T PUT IT
IN THE FRONT WINDOW.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA TAKE IT OVER
THERE NEAR THE PITA MACHINE.
WHOA.
OKAY, SO DON'T LAUGH.
SO WHAT IS THAT
BEHIND YOU?
THE PITA MACHINE.
(mouths words)
WE PUT THE CORNMEAL.
OKAY.
SO THIS IS
THE PIES.
SO THAT'S IT--A LITTLE BIT
OF OIL ON YOUR HANDS.
PUT IT IN
THE CORN FLOUR.
SO THAT KEEPS IT
FROM STICKING TOGETHER.
MAKE IT A LITTLE BIT, LIKE,
MORE CRUNCHY AND FLUFFY.
CRUNCHY AND FLUFFY.
YES.
LET'S PARTY.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT.
STRETCH IT
A LITTLE BIT.
LOOK HOW THIN
SHE'S MAKING THAT.
WE NEED A PILLOW
FOR, UM...
OH, TO PUT IT ON.
WHERE DID THE PILLOW
COME FROM?
FROM ISRAEL.
DO YOU SEE THAT?
IT'S SO COOL.
(whispering)
THE PITA MACHINE.
THAT'S IT? THAT'S
THE WHOLE PROCESS?
YES.
ALL THAT?
I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW THIN YOU MADE IT.
IT'S, LIKE,
"NEW YORK TIMES" THIN.
(laughs) MMM.
IT'S AWESOME.
THE CORNMEAL
ON THE OUTSIDE OF IT
GIVES IT A LITTLE MORE TEXTURE.
I LIKE THAT.
THIS IS HUMMUS
AND OLIVE OIL?
MM-HMM.
YOU MAKE THE HUMMUS?
MMM. YOU GOT
TO COME TRY THIS.
(Gazala) TABLE ONE,
HUMMUS PITA.
LOOK AT
HOW THIN IT IS.
MM-HMM.
AND IT'S
SO FRESH.
OH, ISN'T THAT
NICE?
MM-HMM.
THIS COMES FROM
A MAGIC PITA MACHINE
THAT WAS HAMMERED
BY ELVES IN HER COUNTRY.
(bell dings)
(Gazala) HALABI,
TABLE SEVEN.
IT'S JUST VERY TRADITIONAL.
THEY KEEP TO, LIKE, THEIR STYLE.
IT'S REALLY WORTH TRYING,
'CAUSE ONCE YOU TRY IT,
YOU'LL BE A REGULAR.
TO SEE HOW
YOU TREAT FOOD
AND THE RESPECT
THAT YOU PAY FOR FOOD
AND THE SMILE THAT YOU HAVE
ABOUT THE FOOD YOU MAKE
AND THE WAY YOU
INTRODUCE THIS TO PEOPLE,
I-I-I CAN'T TELL YOU
HOW HAPPY I AM FOR YOU.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
PLEASURE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
THIS SHOULD BE
INTERESTING.
WE'RE HEADED
TO LAS VEGAS, NEVADA,
FOR AN ASIAN SPIN...
MIYAGI BURGER.
ON BURGERS...
IN THE BURGER WORLD,
THIS IS burgerbomb.com.
AND FRIES.
THIS SMACKS YOU
IN THE FACE
AND RUNS AROUND
AND KICKS YOU IN THE BUTT.
♪♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN VEGAS,
AND I'M LOOKING FOR WHAT?
SOME TRIPLE "D" JOINTS,
SO WHO DO I CALL?
MY A.T.O.
FRATERNITY BROTHER DALLY.
HE SAYS, "MAN, I'VE GOT A JOINT
THAT'S ABOUT
A MILE OFF THE STRIP
AND A COUPLE BLOCKS FROM MY
HOUSE, AND THEY ARE ROCKING
THE ASIAN-INFUSED
GOURMET BURGERS.
GOURMET BURGERS?
MY MOUTH'S WATERING ALREADY.
THIS IS BACHI BURGER.
MIYAGI BURGER.
THEY'RE NOT YOUR REGULAR
BURGER JOINT BURGERS.
'CAUSE OWNER LORIN WATADA KNOWS
IN A CITY LIKE VEGAS
YOU GOTTA STAND OUT.
EVERYONE ELSE
IS DOING BURGERS.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE AN IMPACT
WITH OUR FLAVORS
AND BRING SOME UNIQUENESS
TO THE TABLE.
SOME OF THE INGREDIENTS
ARE PRETTY COMPLEX.
LIKE APPLE VINAIGRETTE
ON THE MISO BURGER,
GARLIC CHILI AIOLI
ON KIKI'S BURGER,
AND MIXING PORK AND SHRIMP
INTO THIS POPULAR HYBRID.
"BANH-MI" BURGER.
LORIN'S TAKE ON THE CLASSIC
VIETNAMESE SANDWICH.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD
A BANH MI SANDWICH?
(chuckles) HOW DO YOU THINK
I GOT LIKE THIS?
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF BANH MI SANDWICHES.
I'M DOWN WITH THE FLAVORS.
I'M DOWN WITH THE TEXTURES.
I THOUGHT IT WOULD BE COOL
TO TAKE THOSE FLAVORS
AND PUT THIS INTO A BURGER.
OKAY, GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH SOME
ALL-NATURAL,
FRESH-GROUND ANGUS CHUCK.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE
A LITTLE BIT OF BEEF IN THERE,
BECAUSE IT IS A BURGER,
AFTER ALL. FRESH-GROUND PORK.
THIS IS A DUROC PORK.
IN TERMS OF FLAVOR PROFILE,
I LIKE IT THE BEST.
NICE AND RICH, GOOD FAT.
SOME DICED SHRIMP.
THE SHRIMP'S GOING IN
WITH THE MEAT?
YEP.
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF PANKO BREADCRUMBS.
A LITTLE PANKO, OKAY.
A WHOLE EGG.
FOR SOME BINDER.
7 OUNCES--
RIGHT ON THE MONEY.
WE DON'T WANT TO PRESS
TOO HARD.
JUST ENOUGH TO GET IT
INTO THE MOLD.
DON'T WANT TO MAKE IT HARD
AND PUSH THE FAT OUT.
POP IT OUT JUST LIKE THAT.
OKAY, NOW WE'RE MAKING
THE BANH MI MARINADE
FOR THE BURGER.
YES.
SUGAR, FISH SAUCE,
YELLOW THAI CURRY--
WHISK THIS TOGETHER--
LIME JUICE...
SHALLOTS.
SLICED GARLIC.
OH, MY FAVORITE.
LEMONGRASS.
A LITTLE LEMONGRASS.
A LITTLE BIT OF TURMERIC.
REALLY? GET SOME
OF THAT EXTRA COLOR?
YES. FINISH OFF WITH OUR
HERBS--THAI BASIL, CILANTRO.
THAI CHILI.
NICE AND SPICY.
GIVE IT A WHISK.
OH, THAT'S KILLER.
OHH. LET'S GET THIS BURGER
GOING, DUDE.
TAKE OUR FRESH PATTY. LET'S
WALK OVER HERE BY THE GRILL.
A GOOD AMOUNT
OF SALT AND PEPPER.
DIP IT
IN THE BANH MI MARINADE.
ONTO THE GRILL.
YOU KNOW WHAT THIS IS?
NO.
IT'S CURED PORK LOAF.
SET THIS
IN OUR HOUSE MARINADE--
WATER, SAKE, SOY,
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
OKAY.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS
RIGHT ON THE GRILL AS WELL.
I SEAR OFF BOTH SIDES, THEN GO
BACK IN THE MARINADE AGAIN.
STICK IT BACK ON.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
BUN IS ON THE GRILL.
IT'S A TAIWANESE
SWEET BREAD BUN.
WE'RE GONNA HIT THIS
WITH JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SEASONING RIGHT AT THE END,
AND THE BURGER'S DONE.
OUR GRILLED PORK--
SET IT RIGHT ON TOP.
THIS IS OUR CURRY AIOLI,
OKAY?
CURRY AIOLI?
CURRY AIOLI. HERBS--WE'VE GOT
SOME VIETNAMESE MINT IN HERE,
CILANTRO, THAI BASIL.
PICKLED VEGETABLES
RIGHT HERE.
PICKLED DAIKON
AND PICKLED CARROT.
OKAY.
AND SOME FRESH
GREEN LEAF LETTUCE.
TOP OF OUR BUN.
THERE YOU GO--
THE "BANH-MI" BURGER.
DUDE.
LOOK AT THAT.
DUROC PORK,
ANGUS GROUND BEEF,
THE SHRIMP
COOKED TOGETHER
IN THE BANH MI MARINADE.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
I HONESTLY HAVE BEEN
ANTICIPATING THE FLAVORS OF THIS
SINCE I HEARD
ABOUT THE PLACE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE A GRIN
LIKE THAT. HMM.
IT'S GOOD STUFF. YEAH.
THE BUN'S OUTSTANDING.
IT'S THIN.
IT'S GOT GOOD TEXTURE.
IT'S GOT GOOD CHEW.
I AM TELLING YOU WHAT--
THIS WILL BE AN EXPERIENCE
YOU WILL NEVER FORGET.
LORIN...
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
IN THE BURGER WORLD,
THIS IS burgerbomb.com.
(chuckles)
TASTE OF SWEETNESS IN THE BURGER
BUT WITH THE SPICINESS
OF THE AIOLI--
IT'S REALLY DELICIOUS.
IT'S ALMOST KIND OF LIKE
DIM SUM IN A BURGER.
THAT'S 'CAUSE THEY'RE HIS TAKE
ON THE FOOD HE ATE AS A KID.
I GREW UP IN HAWAII. WE HAD
A LOT OF LOCAL BURGER PLACES.
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT FROM WHAT
THEY DO HERE ON THE MAINLAND.
EVERYTHING IS ASIAN-INSPIRED--
FLAVORS FROM PACIFIC RIM,
FLAVORS FROM JAPAN, CHINA,
THAILAND, VIETNAM.
BUT HE'S PUTTING ASIAN SPIN
ON MORE THAN JUST THE BURGERS.
PORK BELLY STEAMED BUNS.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE WHOLE PORK BELLY.
OKAY.
WE CUT THIS IN HALF.
GOT IT PORTIONED OUT.
SALT AND PEPPER.
GET THE PAN NICE AND HOT.
SOME VEGETABLE OIL.
SEAR OFF THAT FAT.
YOU GET A NICE BROWN CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE.
ALL THE WAY AROUND?
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
SO WE'RE GONNA SEAR
ALL FOUR SIDES OF THIS.
WE PUT THIS IN THE PAN
FOR BRAISING.
OKAY.
WE'VE GOT SOME
SHAOXING COOKING WINE,
JUST ENOUGH TO COVER
THE PORK BELLY.
THIS IS CHINESE WINE?
THIS IS SIMILAR TO SHERRY.
OKAY.
NOW CHOPPED GARLIC,
OUR SLICED GINGER,
STAR ANISE.
MMM.
LICORICE FLAVOR.
I LOVE THAT SMELL.
NEXT UP--OHH,
THESE ARE MY FAVORITE.
THIS IS OUR
SZECHUAN PEPPERCORNS.
AND THESE
ARE THE DRIED SHALLOTS.
GREEN ONIONS STEMS
WE ADD FOR FLAVOR.
OKAY.
AND THEN CILANTRO STEMS.
HOW DOES THIS LOOK?
IT LOOKS FANTASTIC.
JUST ENOUGH WATER
TO COVER IT.
YEAH.
AND ARE WE GONNA USE THIS
BRAISING LIQUID LATER
FOR ANYTHING?
WE USE THAT AS THE BASE FOR
OUR SAUCE FOR OUR PORK BELLY.
WE'RE GONNA COVER IT
WITH SOME TINFOIL.
ABOUT 450 DEGREES
FOR 5 HOURS.
IT'S GONNA COME OUT
JUST BARELY HOLDING TOGETHER.
COOL IT OVERNIGHT.
LET IT CONGEAL.
YEAH.
AND THEN WE SLICE IT.
WE HAVE OUR PORK BELLY.
IT'S PORTIONED OUT.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT AND PEPPER, SEASON IT.
SO THIS POTATO STARCH.
WE'RE JUST GONNA DREDGE THIS
IS THE POTATO STARCH.
WE'RE GONNA GO INSIDE
THE DEEP FRYER
FOR ABOUT 30 SECONDS.
NEXT UP.
AND WE'RE GONNA FINISH
OUR PORK BELLY
IN THE BRAISING LIQUID.
THAT WE STRAINED.
IT GOES
INTO OUR HOT SAUTé PAN.
IT REDUCES AND FORMS A GLAZE
AROUND THE PORK BELLY.
RIGHT.
WE WANT
THAT NICE LACQUERED LOOK.
SO AS THE PORK IS COOKING,
WE'RE STEAMING OUR BUNS.
PUT THEM IN THE STEAMER
FOR ABOUT SEVEN MINUTES.
FANTASTIC.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
A SANDWICH.
STICK THE PORK INSIDE
JUST LIKE THAT.
OHH.
WE GOT SOME BOILED EGG HERE,
GOT SOME SLICED RED RADISH,
GREEN ONIONS
AND SOME CILANTRO,
ASIAN-STYLE MIXED GREENS,
THE CHINESE BLACK VINAIGRETTE.
HOISIN GONE WILD.
ALL RIGHT,
HOW'S IT LOOK?
YOU JUST HAVE SO MUCH
GOING ON
THAT IT LOOKS TOO GOOD
TO ACTUALLY BITE INTO.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
I GOT TO INTRODUCE YOU THE CAT
THAT TOLD ME ABOUT THIS PLACE.
THAT'S DALY,
MY FRATERNITY BROTHER.
WENT TO COLLEGE
AT U.N.L.V. TOGETHER.
AND HE LIVES, LITERALLY,
HOW FAR?
OH, ABOUT 40 FEET.
YEAH, PRETTY CLOSE.
THIS IS NO BURGER.
NO.
BUT THIS IS
THE KIND OF FOOD?
THIS IS THE KIND OF FRESH FOOD
THAT YOU'RE GONNA LOVE.
OH, HERE WE GO.
GET A LITTLE DIP.
MMM.
WHAT DID I TELL YOU?
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
FRESH, GREAT, TASTY--
CAN'T GO WRONG.
THAT'S RIGHTEOUS.
THE PORK IS REALLY RICH.
THE STEAMED BUN--IT'S LIGHT,
BUT IT'S DENSE. OUTSTANDING.
UP NEXT...
CHEF, WHAT DO YOU RECOMMEND
WE'RE GONNA TRY NEXT?
MY FAVORITE IS
THE OXTAIL CHILI CHEESE FRIES.
IT'S OUT OF SIGHT.
OXTAIL CHILI CHEESE FRIES.
AWESOME. DALY,
THANKS, BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER,
YOU KNOW, YOU COME TO VEGAS,
YOU ALWAYS GOT TO ASK ME
WHERE ARE THE PLACES TO GO.
I'LL TALK TO YOU, BUD.
(whistles) YEAH.
ABOUT 5 MILES SOUTH
OF THE VEGAS STRIP
AT A PLACE
CALLED BACHI BURGER...
"BANH-MI" BURGER.
CHEF LORIN WATADA
INFUSING AMERICAN BURGERS
WITH ASIAN FLAVOR.
YOU GOTTA GET A BACHI BURGER.
BUT WHAT'S A BURGER
WITHOUT SOME FRIES,
ESPECIALLY CHILI CHEESE FRIES?
THEY'RE NOT YOUR REGULAR
EVERYDAY BALLPARK
CHILI CHEESE FRIES.
I KNOW
WHAT SOME OF THIS IS.
OXTAIL.
(whistles)
THIS IS THE ENTIRE TAIL
RIGHT HERE.
SO CHILI CHEESE FRIES
ISN'T JUST ENOUGH FOR YOU?
YOU HAVE TO MAKE AN OXTAIL
RAGU TO GO ON TOP OF IT?
I HAD TO DO
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
AND YOU COOK THIS STUFF DOWN,
AND IT JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH.
OKAY, HIT IT.
SIMMERING WATER--
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT IN THERE.
I'M GONNA TAKE A WHOLE OXTAIL...
NOT CUT IT UP AT ALL,
JUST GONNA GO IN.
NOPE.
WE'RE GONNA BRAISE THESE
ON A LOW HEAT FOR FIVE HOURS
TILL PRETTY MUCH THE MEAT
IS FALLING OFF THE BONE.
ARE WE GONNA DO ANYTHING
WITH THE BONES AFTERWARDS?
WE RESERVE THAT
FOR A DEMI-GLACE.
OF COURSE WE DO, 'CAUSE
YOU'RE AT THIS BURGER JOINT.
WE USE EVERYTHING.
THEY USE EVERYTHING.
NEXT UP?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR OXTAIL CHILI.
OKAY, LET'S BUILD IT.
WE GOT OUR POT
GOING RIGHT HERE.
I'VE ALREADY HEATED IT UP
WITH SOME OIL INSIDE.
ONIONS FIRST.
APPLEWOOD-SMOKED BACON--
SAUTé THAT OFF TOGETHER--
CHOPPED JALAPEÑOS,
CILANTRO AND BROWN SUGAR...
OKAY.
GARLIC POWDER,
ONION POWDER.
A LOT OF GROUND OREGANO.
WELL, IT'S HALF GROUND CUMIN
AS WELL.
PAPRIKA
AND OUR CHILI POWDER.
WHEW!
GIVE THAT A STIR.
DIJON MUSTARD,
CHILI PASTE,
THEN OUR TOMATO PASTE.
OKAY, NEXT UP.
NEXT, WE GOT OUR BEER
RIGHT HERE,
OUR BRAISING LIQUID
FROM OUR OXTAILS.
THE OXTAIL
FANTASTIC GELATINOUS.
SHREDDED OXTAIL MEAT
THAT WE CHOPPED UP.
LOOK AT ALL THAT.
LITTLE BITS OF FAT,
THE OXTAIL--SUPER FLAVOR.
SOME CHICKEN STOCK.
OUR DARK CHOCOLATE CHIPS.
THIS, I HAVEN'T
SEEN BEFORE.
I KNOW HOW I LOVE IT
IN MOLE.
THAT WAS EXACTLY
THE INSPIRATION.
OKAY.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
RED WINE VINEGAR.
RED AND WINE BEANS, WHICH HAVE
BEEN SOAKED OVERNIGHT.
AND THIS IS OUR
3-DAY OXTAIL DEMI-GLACE.
MAN HAS ISSUES.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
OKAY, NOW HOW LONG WE GONNA
LET THIS COOK DOWN?
20 MINUTES.
THAT'S IT? AND THEN
WE'RE GOOD TO GO?
YEAH. THEN WE'RE GOOD
TO GO.
LADLE TO A SAUTé PAN.
MONTEREY JACK CHEESE
RIGHT ON THE TOP,
SOME FRESH SLICED JALAPEÑOS.
THIS GOES RIGHT INTO THE OVEN
JUST TO MELT THE CHEESE.
GOT OUR NICE CRISPY
FRENCH FRIES READY TO GO.
WE GOT THIS CHILI
COMING OUT OF THE OVEN.
SLIDES RIGHT OUT
ON TOP.
THIS IS A GARLIC CHILI AIOLI,
ALL RIGHT?
GREEN ONIONS, FRESH CILANTRO,
OKAY, GOOD, AND THAT'S ALL
THAT WE'RE PUTTING ON IT.
AND THEN WE GOT ONE LAST THING--
SUNNY-SIDE UP EGG
AND DIG RIGHT INTO IT,
AND ALL THE YOLK
RUNS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
YOU'RE "YOLKING."
NO, I'M NOT. (chuckles)
DO YOU EAT IT WITH A FORK?
DO YOU EAT IT WITH YOUR HANDS?
NO, YOU JUST DIG IN.
LOOK AT THAT.
BROTHER, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
IT'S LIKE I SAY--"IF YOU'RE
GONNA EAT STUFF LIKE THIS,
EAT THE BEST."
THIS IS SCRATCH-MADE,
HANDMADE, OUTSTANDING,
REAL DEAL,
WAY-IT-SHOULD-BE CHILI.
DO YOU HEAR
WHAT I'M SAYING?
IT'S DIFFERENT FROM
ANY CHILI CHEESE FRIES
THAT YOU ORDER.
DUDE, THE BOMB.
THIS SMACKS YOU IN THE FACE
AND RUNS AROUND
AND KICKS YOU IN THE BUTT.
NOW YOU GOTTA SAY SOMETHING
CLEVER TO THE CAMERA.
AT BACHI BURGER,
WE GO BIG
OR WE GO HOME.
COMING UP...
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
WE'RE HEADED
TO RICHARDSON, TEXAS,
FOR A TASTE OF WHAT ELSE?
CHICKEN SHAWARMA
FLAVOR CONE.
WHY DOESN'T IT SAY THAT
ON THE BILLBOARD?
LEBANESE.
YOU'RE IN TEXAS, DUDE,
AND YOU'RE EATING
IN A MIDDLE EASTERN
MEDITERRANEAN RESTAURANT.
AND I LOVE IT, MAN.
YOU KNOW HOW EVERYBODY
HAS THEIR G.P.S. SETTINGS--
YOU KNOW, POINTS OF INTEREST,
YOU KNOW, BANK APPROACHING
OR GAS STATION OR MOVIE THEATER?
ME, ON MY SPECIAL EDITION
TRIPLE "D" FLAVOR TOWN G.P.S.,
I HAVE IT SET TO LET ME KNOW
WHEN SHAWARMA IS APPROACHING.
SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA!
(alarm blaring)
SO HERE I AM IN RICHARDSON,
12 MILES
OUTSIDE OF DALLAS, TEXAS,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT THAT I HEAR
IS ROCKIN' THE SHAWARMA.
THIS IS AFRAH.
SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA, SHAWARMA!
CHICKEN SHAWARMA.
AND BREAD.
IT JUST HAS AN AMAZING FLAVOR.
(woman) TABBOULI SALAD.
I'M FROM THE MIDDLE EAST.
IT TASTES
LIKE SOME OF THE RECIPES
ARE EXACTLY LIKE MY MOM
USED TO MAKE.
IT'S ALWAYS DELICIOUS.
I HAVE TO COME HERE AT LEAST
ONCE A WEEK OR I'LL DIE.
DIE?
YEAH, I'LL JUST
STRAIGHT-UP DIE.
I LOVE THE PASSION
FOR A FAMILY-RUN JOINT
THAT STARTED AS A PASTRY SHOP
IN '01.
BUT THE ELHORR BROTHERS,
THEY DECIDED TO GO BIGGER.
THERE WAS A BIG DEMAND
FOR FOOD
WHEN WE STARTED OPENING
AS A SWEET SHOP.
SO GRADUALLY, WE STARTED ADDING
LITTLE ITEMS HERE AND THERE
FROM MY MOM'S RECIPE.
KAFTA PLATE
WITH HUMMUS READY.
VERY UNIQUE FOOD. YOU KNOW, YOU
DON'T SEE IT ON EVERY CORNER.
WELL, THAT'S WHY I HAVE IT
PROGRAMMED IN MY G.P.S.
FALAFEL IS READY
FOR PICKUP.
YOU'RE IN TEXAS, DUDE.
TEXAS, DUDE.
AND YOU'RE EATING IN
A MIDDLE EASTERN
MEDITERRANEAN RESTAURANT.
AND I LOVE IT, MAN.
CHICKEN SHAWARMA.
I DO GET THE SHAWARMA
EVERY TIME I COME.
IT'S JUST
SO EXTREMELY FLAVORFUL
THAT EVERY MOUTHFUL
IS JUST AN EXPERIENCE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
CHICKEN SHAWARMA.
WHAT DOES SHAWARMA MEAN?
IT'S A TURKISH WORD,
SHAWARMA.
THIS IS WHAT SHAWARMA IS--
IT'S THE MEAT
ON A--STACKED ON TOP
OF EACH OTHER.
WE HAVE
THE SHAWARMA SPICES.
WHAT IS IN
THE SHAWARMA SPICES?
CAYENNE, PAPRIKA.
AND IT'S CALLED
SHAWARMA SPICES?
IT'S CALLED
CHICKEN SHAWARMA SPICES.
IF ANYBODY WANTS TO MAKE
CHICKEN SHAWARMA WITH SPICES,
HE GOES WITH THIS ONE.
YOU DON'T USE THIS?
YOU DON'T HAVE SHAWARMA.
OKAY.
WE HAVE CITRIC ACID
TO GIVE IT A LEMONY TASTE,
SALT, GROUND CORIANDER,
TOMATO SAUCE,
OLIVE OIL--100%--
AND THE REST IS WATER.
WE HAVE A MIX OF ONIONS,
GARLIC, CORIANDER--FRESH.
AND THAT GOES
ON THE CHICKEN?
THAT GOES ON THE CHICKEN.
HOW LONG WILL IT MARINATE?
AT LEAST 12 TO 24 HOURS.
12 TO 24 HOURS.
SO HOW BIG OF A PLATFORM--
IT'S NOT GONNA COME
ALL THE WAY OUT?
IT'S GONNA BE--
IT'S STILL GONNA COME--
I'M STILL GONNA SHAPE IT
LIKE A CONE.
CHICKEN SHAWARMA
FLAVOR CONE.
YES.
WHY DOESN'T IT SAY THAT
ON THE BILLBOARD?
(chuckles)
SO JUST KEEP
STACKING IT UP.
KEEP STACKING IT UP.
PRESSING IT DOWN.
NOW I'M GONNA
PRESS IT DOWN.
THAT'S THE MANHOLE COVER
PRESS?
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA START
SHAPING IT UP.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO WITH
THOSE EXTRA CHUNKS OF CHICKEN?
THEY GO BACK HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA
STACK THEM ON THERE.
STACK IT IN THERE.
AND THEN YOU'RE GONNA USE
THAT MEAT TO HOLD THAT ON THERE.
RIGHT.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE GOT IT ON.
THIGH MEAT ON TOP.
OKAY.
FAT, AND WE'RE READY
TO GO TO THE...
WELL, WE NEED
TO GARNISH IT FIRST.
AND HOW MUCH WEIGHT
DO YOU THINK THAT IS?
THAT'S ABOUT 65, 70 POUNDS.
LIFT WITH YOUR LEGS,
NOT WITH YOUR BACK.
AND HOW LONG WILL
IT GO ON THE ROTISSERIE
BEFORE WE START EATING IT?
20 TO 25 MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, SO NICE AND BROWN.
NOW IT'S GOOD TO GO?
VERY THIN.
YOU HAVE TO MIX IT
WITH THE...
SOME OF THE BASTING JUICES.
EXACTLY.
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
AND THAT'S THE DEAL.
MMM.
IT'S TENDER.
IT'S JUICY.
IT'S SUPER FLAVORFUL--
NOT OVERSEASONED,
NOT OVERSPICED.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT ALL THAT CRUST.
KIND OF LIKE EVERY PIECE
HAS A CRUNCH EXTERIOR TO IT,
AND THEN YOU SEE HERE,
AS SOON AS MINE GOT CUT OFF,
IT'S STARTING TO BROWN AGAIN,
SO THE NEXT ORDER,
WHEN THEY COME AND TAKE IT OFF,
IT'S GONNA BE THE BOMB AGAIN.
MMM.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL, MAN.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CHICKEN SHAWARMA.
THIS IS PROBABLY THE BEST
SHAWARMA I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S ROCKIN' SHAWARMA.
IT'S AWESOME.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
A SHAWARMA COMA IN A LITTLE BIT.
I LIKE HOW HE WEARS HIS HAT
LIKE A COWBOY.
(laughs) YEAH, WELL...
HE'S LIKE THE LEBANESE
JOHN WAYNE.
(together) I'LL TELL YOU.
(as John Wayne)
YA PILGRIM.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
LIKE IT?
DUDE, DO I LIKE IT?
HARD TO TELL. (laughs)
I'M SORRY. IF I COULD GET IT
IN MY PIEHOLE ANY FASTER...
GO TO COMMERCIAL.