HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
AFRAID IT'S COMING
MY WAY.
YOU SHOULD BE WORRIED.
(chuckles)
IT'S ALL ABOUT FINDING
REAL-DEAL FLAVOR.
HIT IT.
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
WOW! WOW! WOW!
THE CARIBBEAN SPOT...
GETTIN' ALL
WITCH DOCTOR ON ME.
(laughs)
KICKIN' BACK WITH THE TASTE
OF TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO.
FIRE TRUCK!
IN DALLAS, TEXAS...
THIS IS WHERE
IT'S GONNA GET COOL.
A NEAPOLITAN PIZZA JOINT...
HA HA!
MAKING ROOM
FOR THE PORK ON THE PIZZA...
THIS IS A WHIRLWIND.
THIS IS--
THIS IS--THIS--AHH!
AND THE PASTA.
THAT'S WHAT THEY NEED
TO START SELLING.
PORK-A-LICIOUS.
AND IN AUSTIN, TEXAS,
THE ITTY-BITTY DINER...
IT'S 26 SEATS AND 700 SQUARE
FEET, AND IT'S ROCKIN'.
GOING BIG WITH SCRATCH-MADE
CLASSICS.
IF YOU DON'T MAKE
A SCRATCH-MADE BISCUIT HERE,
YOU PROBABLY GET
RUN OUT OF TOWN.
EXACTLY.
I SAW THAT POSTER.
(laughs)
YEAH, OKAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN DALLAS, TEXAS,
IN A VERY WELL-KNOWN
TRIPLE "D" AREA
KNOWN AS DEEP ELLUM.
NOW WE WERE HERE A FEW YEARS AGO
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
AT A JOINT THAT'S SERVING UP
GREAT BURGERS WITH CRAZY NAMES.
THE BOYS FROM TWISTED ROOT.
AND RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET,
THE NEW KID ON THE BLOCK,
SERVING UP
VERA PIZZA NAPOLETANA,
THIS IS CANE ROSSO!
LET'S GET READY TO MANGIA!
MARGHERITA'S DOWN.
BEST PIZZA IN TOWN.
ALWAYS FRESH INGREDIENTS.
DELIA, PICK UP!
JAY HAS SUCH A PASSION
FOR NEAPOLITAN PIZZA.
FIRING THE CHE CHAZZO.
YEAH, THAT AIN'T NO JOKE,
'CAUSE OWNER AND CHEF
JAY JERRIER
GAVE UP HIS DAY JOB...
I WAS IN, UH, I.T.
AND TECHNICAL SALES.
I'M SORRY.
BUILT AN OVEN IN HIS BACKYARD,
AND GOT CERTIFIED TO SLING
NEAPOLITAN PIES.
AND WHEN HE OPENED HIS OWN
PIZZA JOINT IN 2011,
HE NAMED IT
AFTER A LONG-LOST FRIEND.
IT'S NAMED AFTER MY FIRST DOG.
HUNGARIAN POINTERS, OR VIZSLAS,
THEY HAVE RED FUR,
AND "CANE ROSSO" MEANS
"RED DOG" IN ITALIAN.
YOU HAVE DOGS NOW?
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE
GUS AND DELIA,
WHO ARE HONORED ON THE MENU.
SO HERE'S YOUR DELIA.
WE GOT THE DELIA, WITH ARUGULA,
GRAPE TOMATOES,
AND BACON MARMALADE--
IT'S LIKE BACON JELLY.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
ALL RIGHT,
SO FOR THE BACON MARMALADE,
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL IN THE PAN.
LOCALLY MADE BACON.
(sizzling)
(tapping)
CAN'T LET THAT GO TO WASTE.
LET IT RENDER DOWN.
ADD SOME MINT SHALLOTS,
GARLIC, CALABRIAN CHILES.
MMM.
THEY'RE NOT AS SPICY
AS JALAPEÑOS,
NOT AS IN-YOUR-FACE.
A LITTLE VINEGAR TO THEM.
YEAH. CHERRY VINEGAR.
CHILI PASTE.
FINISH IT OFF WITH SOME SUGAR.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA LET THIS--
SIT THERE AND COOK DOWN.
SIT THERE AND COOK DOWN
UNTIL IT GETS TO LIKE
A JELLY OR MARMALADE-LIKE
CONSISTENCY.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE
GONNA MAKE OUR DOUGH.
WE START OFF WITH WATER.
SICILIAN SEA SALT.
WE ADD OUR FIRST BATCH
OF CAPUTO FLOUR.
THE CAPUTO FLOUR--
00, HIGH-GLUTEN FLOUR.
OLD MAN RIVER HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
(speaks indistinctly)
I KNOW.
NICE AND SLOW AND STEADY.
WE'LL GIVE THIS A MIX,
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR NEXT BATCH OF FLOUR,
AND THEN THE YEAST.
WE MIX IT TOTALLY
FOR 25 MINUTES,
THEN WE'LL BALL IT UP, LET IT
PROOF AT ROOM TEMPERATURE
8 TO 12 HOURS.
PROOFED. IT'S READY TO GO.
JUST GIVE IT A LITTLE STRETCH.
WOW, THAT IS JUST
THIN AND FAST, MAN!
WE'RE GONNA ASSEMBLE
OUR DELIA PIZZA.
FRESH MOZZARELLA.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR BACON MARMALADE.
ROASTED GRAPE TOMATOES.
WE NEED A LITTLE
SQUIRT OF OLIVE OIL.
THEN WE ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF BASIL.
NOW IT IS READY FOR THE OVEN.
GOING INTO AN OVEN
AT WHAT TEMP?
ABOUT 900 DEGREES.
900-DEGREE OVEN. THIS IS
WHERE IT'S GONNA GET COOL.
HA HA!
LIKE THAT.
GANGSTER.
NOW WHAT KINDA WOOD
ARE WE BURNIN'?
TEXAS OAK.
SO THIS IS 60 TO 70 SECONDS.
READY TO GO.
LOOK AT THAT!
WE ADD OUR LITTLE ARUGULA.
A BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
IT'S READY TO GO TO A TABLE.
(mouth full) TO BREAK IT
DOWN FOR YOU,
THE SWEET, SMOKEY,
SALTY--AND NOT TOO SALTY--
BACON MARMALADE THAT GOES IN.
THE ARUGULA
FOR A LITTLE PEPPER.
THE LITTLE BIT OF CHAR
FROM THE CRUST
GIVES IT
THAT RUSTIC APPEAL.
THIS IS A WHIRLWIND.
THIS IS--
THIS IS--THIS--AHH!
(mouth full)
I'M AT A LOSS FOR WORDS.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
DELIA'S UP.
HERE YOU GO, GENTLEMEN.
IT'S YOUR DELIA FOR YOU.
IT'S SO GOOD.
IT'S SO SALTY AND PILLOWY.
FRESH PASTA GOING DOWN.
AND PIZZA'S NOT THE ONLY THING
THEY'RE DISHING UP.
PASTA'S REALLY GREAT HERE
BECAUSE IT'S HANDMADE.
PASTA AMATRICIANA'S UP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR FRESH PASTA FOR OUR
PASTA AMATRICIANA.
THIS IS THE SAME FLOUR
WE USE FOR OUR PIZZA.
SUPER HIGH-GLUTEN FLOUR.
GONNA GET A LOT OF
GREAT CHEW OUT OF THAT.
WE ADD THE EGGS,
PINCH OF SALT,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA START
MUSHING THIS TOGETHER.
THIS IS HOW YOU DO IT EVERY DAY
FOR YOUR RESTAURANT?
EVERY MORNING.
GONNA START ADDING
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER?
THEN WE'LL WRAP IT,
STORE IT,
BRING IT OUT,
START RUNNING IT THROUGH.
AFRAID IT'S COMING
MY WAY.
YOU SHOULD BE WORRIED.
OKAY.
(chuckles)
START RUNNING IT THROUGH.
AND WE KEEP IT A LITTLE THICKER
'CAUSE WE COOK IT AL DENTE.
NOW ARE WE GONNA LET THIS
REST BEFORE WE CUT IT,
OR ARE WE GONNA GO
STRAIGHT TO CUTTING?
WE CAN CUT IT
STRAIGHT THROUGH.
(clicking)
KEEP GOING. YOU GOT IT.
FEEL THE PAIN.
FEEL THE BURN.
(clicking)
OKAY. SO WE LET THIS DRY,
AND WE'RE READY TO GO?
ABSOLUTELY.
SO WE MAKE OUR PANCETTA.
LITTLE PORK BELLY?
LITTLE PORK BELLY.
A LITTLE SEA SALT,
AND WE JUST KINDA WANT IT
TO LOOK LIKE SNOW.
SO WE'LL JUST RUB THIS DOWN
ON BOTH SIDES.
YOU'RE GONNA GET ALL THIS
GREAT, UNCTUOUS,
PIG-A-NICIOUS FLAVOR THAT'S
GONNA COME OUT OF THE, UH...
IT'S A NEW WORD.
WORK WITH IT.
ALL RIGHT, SO AFTER WE'VE
LET THE PORK BELLY
CURE FOR THREE DAYS, WE'LL
PUT IT IN A 325-DEGREE OVEN
ANYWHERE FROM
60 TO 90 MINUTES.
SO WE WILL PULL THIS
OFF THE THING
AND WE WILL JUST--
HO, HO, HO.
GOTTA GET RIGHT UNDER THAT.
THAT'S WHAT THEY NEED
TO START SELLING AT THE FAIR.
GET THESE KIDS OFF THE CANDY.
MMM!
(mouth full) GO RIGHT AHEAD.
DO WHATEVER YOU GOTTA DO NOW.
WE'RE GONNA DICE THIS UP.
IT'S NICE, IT'S CRUNCHY,
IT'S SALTY,
AND THAT'S WHAT REALLY MAKES
THE AMATRICIANA COME TOGETHER.
PORK-A-LICIOUS.
PUT A LITTLE EXTRA VIRGIN
OLIVE OIL.
PANCETTA. A FEW ONIONS
IN THERE.
TOUCH OF PASTA WATER.
FORTIFIED SAN MARZANO
TOMATOES.
FORTIFIED WITH A LITTLE...
OREGANO, BASIL.
(smacks lips) MMM.
A LITTLE CHILI FLAKE.
A BIT OF PARMESAN. AND WE'RE
GONNA DROP OUR PASTA.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT COOK
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE.
WE'RE GONNA HIT THIS WITH
A LITTLE RED CHILI FLAKE.
WE TAKE OUR PASTA,
DRAIN IT OFF,
DROP IT IN THE PAN.
LET THAT SAUCE KIND OF
AMALGAMATE TO THAT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA JUST
DROP IT IN A PLATE.
A LITTLE MORE PARMESAN ON TOP
OF THAT, READY TO GO.
IT'S GOT ALL THE RIGHT
PRINCIPALS, MAN.
YOU'VE GOT GREAT PASTA,
WHICH HAS GOT NICE TEXTURE
TO IT, NICE CHEW.
YOU GOT PIG-TASTIC
HOUSE-CURED PANCETTA.
(inhales)
(mouth full) IT'S SIMPLE,
IT'S DELICATE.
DID A GOOD JOB.
ALL RIGHT, DUDE.
BOLOGNESE COMING RIGHT UP.
AND THE AMATRICIANA.
I LOVE THE FRESH TASTE
OF THE PASTA,
AND THE PORK
AND EVERYTHING IN IT.
OVEN'S GOOD AND HOT.
(man) I COME HERE BECAUSE
I REALLY AGREE
WITH JAY'S PHILOSOPHY--
GETTING THE BEST INGREDIENTS,
DOING THE HARD WORK HIMSELF,
AND HE AGREES
THERE'S NO SUCH THING
AS TOO MUCH PORK.
UP NEXT...
CARIBBEAN FOOD AT ITS BEST!
WE'RE HEADING TO MINNEAPOLIS,
MINNESOTA,
TO FEEL THE BURN
OF CARIBBEAN CUISINE.
SUPER-HOTTIE, SMOLDERY
BURNY-MOUTHY?
SKIN GRAFFY FIXY TOPPY ROOFY.
♪♪
SO HERE I AM
IN SOUTH MINNEAPOLIS
ON THE CORNER OF BLOOMINGTON
AND EAST 38th
IN THE POWDERHORN
NEIGHBORHOOD.
AND WHY AM I HERE?
WELL, 'CAUSE WHEN YOUR BUDDY
ANTHONY HERRERA,
NUMBER 64
FOR THE MINNESOTA VIKINGS,
SAYS YOU GOTTA CHECK IT OUT,
YOU CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS MARLA'S
CARIBBEAN CUISINE.
MARLA'S BRINGS THE BEST
OF TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO
TO THE TWIN CITIES.
GOAT AND RICE.
THIS IS AUTHENTIC?
OH, MY GOODNESS, YES.
SOMETHING MARLA JADOONANAN
KNOWS A THING OR TWO ABOUT.
I WAS BORN IN TRINIDAD.
AND RAISED HER FAMILY
ON THE FOOD SHE LOVES.
HERE'S A STEW CHICKEN
WITH FRIED DUMPLINGS.
SHE LEFT HER CAREER
BECAUSE HER PASSION
WAS TO COME DOWN HERE
AND SERVE FOOD
TO THE FOLKS
OF SOUTH MINNEAPOLIS!
ACKEE AND SALTFISH READY.
WHAT DOES ANTHONY EAT
WHEN HE COMES IN?
GOAT.
MMM. I LOVE GOAT.
AND HE ALSO HAS
CURRY BEEF ROTI.
AND THE ROTI IS THE...
IT'S A SORT OF FLATBREAD.
AND SHE'S GOT
A TRINIDADIAN VERSION
FILLED WITH YELLOW SPLIT PEAS
CALLED DHAL POURIE.
AND IT GOES PERFECT
WITH THE CURRY.
MADE WITH POTATOES
AND CHANA, OR CHICKPEAS.
BUT THE ROTI STARTS
WITH YELLOW PEAS.
WE ALSO CALL THIS DHAL.
WE'RE MAKING THE FILLING
FOR THE DHAL POURIE, AND THIS--
OH, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A DOWRY?
NO. DHAL POURIE.
DHAL POURIE.
WE HAVE TO BOIL THIS
WITH TURMERIC, SALT,
AND GARLIC.
SO THEY'RE BOILED AND COOLED.
ROASTED WHOLE CUMIN SEEDS.
THAT SMELLS AWESOME.
NOW WE'LL BE ADDING
THE DHAL.
GARLIC.
HABANERO PEPPER.
AND THEN MORE PEAS?
WHO GETS THIS FUN JOB?
I AM VERY PROTECTIVE
OF MY KITCHEN
AND MY FOOD,
SO I DO IT MYSELF.
(whirring)
YOU DO IT YOURSELF?
GONNA WALK AROUND LIKE POPEYE
WITH ONE BIG ARM.
LOOK AT THIS.
(metal clatters)
(laughter)
THAT'S WHAT YOU GET FOR
MAKING FUN OF MY POPEYE ARM.
(laughs) AHH!
NOW WE HAVE TO SALT IT,
THEN WE HAVE TO TASTE IT.
WOW. THAT TOASTED
REALLY MAKES IT.
SO NOW WE HAVE TO DO
THE CURRY.
CHICKPEAS. OH, HANDS DOWN,
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
DID MY MOM CALL YOU AND SAY,
"GET MORE VEGETARIAN
INTO THIS KID?"
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
IS THAT LIKE AN INTERVENTION?
DR. PHIL'S NOT HERE,
IS HE?
(laughs)
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
YOUR MOM MADE ME PROMISE.
(laughs) THANK YOU. WELL, YOU
REALLY KEPT THAT UNDER WRAPS.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
GONNA SOAK THESE
OVERNIGHT.
WATER. GARLIC. CILANTRO.
FRESH THYME.
A LOT OF THE SAME CHARACTERS.
CHOPPED ONIONS.
SCALLIONS. BAKING POWDER
TO SOFTEN IT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SOYBEAN OIL.
MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
LET IT--LET IT SIT OVERNIGHT.
AND THEN POP IT
IN THE PRESSURE COOKER FOR...
25 MINUTES.
GOT IT.
SO THIS IS MY SPECIAL
BLEND OF CURRY.
ADD SOME GARLIC. ONIONS.
MMM!
CILANTRO.
THEN WE ADD THE WATER.
GONNA MAKE A LITTLE
PASTE WITH IT.
MMM!
CHICKPEAS ARE GOOD.
SO NOW WE ADD THE OIL.
WHOA!
GETTIN' ALL
WITCH DOCTOR ON ME.
(laughs)
I DIG IT.
YOU HAVE TO LET THE WATER,
UM, ABSORB IN THERE,
AND THAT COOKS
THE CURRY DOWN.
CURRY CAN ACTUALLY
TASTE RAW.
OH, I'VE HAD IT RAW
TOO MANY TIMES.
YEAH.
WE ADD THE GARBANZO BEANS,
OR CHANA.
OH, IT SMELLS GREAT!
THESE ARE RAW POTATOES,
AND--
OH, MY GOODNESS.
ADD SOME WATER.
ALL THE FLAVOR
GETS ABSORBED INTO IT.
AWESOME.
WE'LL LET THAT COOK DOWN
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
SO THIS IS THE DOUGH
THAT I NEEDED.
MAKE IT INTO
LITTLE DOUGHBALLS.
OPEN IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
WHAT'S IN THE DOUGH?
BAKING POWDER, SALT,
AND SUGAR.
WE'RE MAKING A WELL SO WE CAN
DO THE FILLING OF THE DHAL.
WE PULL IT TOGETHER.
OH, LOOK AT THAT LITTLE
TWIST THE BASKET.
THERE WE GO.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
ROLL THAT OUT.
THAT'S HISTORY
RIGHT THERE, BABY.
THAT CAME FROM TRINIDAD.
THAT'S OVER 30 YEARS OLD.
ROLL IT.
GENTLY, WITHOUT
POPPING IT.
OH, MY GOSH.
AND YOU STRETCH.
JUST STRETCHING IT OUT.
SO NOW WE HAVE TO TAKE IT
TO THE TOWER.
FIRST WE HAVE TO OIL
THE TOWER.
I GOTTA GET ONE OF THOSE.
NOW WE SLAP IT ON THERE.
OHH!
TORTILLA PIZZA DOUGH
GONE WILD.
AND SEE THE LITTLE BUBBLES
COMING UP THERE?
UH-HUH. I DO.
THAT'S WHEN YOU KNOW
YOU NEED TO TURN.
WHERE HAS THIS BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
OHH, OHH.
IS THIS VEGAN?
YES.
WOW! WOW! WOW!
AND THAT'S IT.
WE'RE ALL DONE.
(mouth full) OHH, THAT'S GOOD!
AND THAT RIGHT THERE--
YOU GOT ME AT "HELLO."
MMM!
HABANERO.
(laughing)
F-F-FIRE TRUCK!
WOW, THAT'S HOT!
CREAMY, GREAT TEXTURE,
SAVORY, SALTY,
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE.
(mouth full) AND LOOK
AT THE GOOSEBUMPS, MAN.
I'M TELLING YOU.
THIS IS ABOUT MY SISTER,
BECAUSE THIS IS HOW MY SISTER
TOLD ME TO ALWAYS EAT.
IN THE TOP THREE BEST
VEGAN DISHES I'VE EVER HAD.
MMM! (mouth full) AND I DON'T
SAY THAT VERY OFTEN.
YOU GUYS KNOW THAT.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
THANK YOU.
AND SHE AIN'T DONE YET.
WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
YOU'RE A MAGIC WOMAN!
UP NEXT...
YOU STOOD RIGHT IN THERE
LIKE A WARRIOR.
THIS FOOD IS RIDICULOUS.
DOWN!
♪♪
WHEN I'M THINKING ABOUT
MINNEAPOLIS,
THE CARIBBEAN IS KIND OF
THE LAST THING ON MY MIND.
BUT MARLA'S
IN THE POWDERHORN NEIGHBORHOOD
IS DEFINITELY
RAISING THE TEMPERATURE
WITH RIGHTEOUS SPICY COOKING
FROM TRINIDAD AND TOBAGO.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS
THE UPPER MIDWEST,
WHERE BLACK PEPPER WAS
THE SPICIEST THING
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
WHEN IT'S 20 BELOW OUTSIDE
ON THE SIDEWALK,
YOU APPRECIATE A TRIP
TO THE CARIBBEAN.
I LOVE THE OXTAILS.
MMM!
SO OXTAIL'S BIG?
VERY BIG.
THEY ATE EVERYTHING
FROM THE ANIMAL.
FROM THE HORN TO THE TAIL.
THIS IS THE TAIL PART.
(imitates lowing)
AND WE HAVE AN ARRAY
OF FRESH SPICES.
VIRTUAL CAVALCADE.
LET'S HIT IT.
BLACK PEPPER.
ONIONS. CILANTRO.
ALLSPICE?
ALLSPICE.
THYME. BAY LEAF.
BAY LEAF.
FRESH GARLIC. ONIONS.
CHOPPED ONIONS.
I FEEL LIKE I'M ALMOST
MAKING A JERK SPICE,
WITHOUT THE HEAT.
YEAH, YOU KNOW, WE USE
A LOT OF THE SAME SPICES...
RIGHT.
IN A LOT OF THE COOKING,
YEAH, SO...
JERK WE'D HAVE SOME CITRUS
AND IT'D HAVE SOME HEAT.
SLICED GINGER.
MARLA'S SPECIAL BLEND.
IS IT PAPRIKA?
WHAT KIND OF PAPRIKA?
MM-HMM-HMM-HMM.
IT IS SMOKED,
AND IT COMES FROM SPAIN.
SMOKED.
WE MIX IT TOGETHER.
WE MARINATE THIS OVERNIGHT.
SO THIS IS ALL GOING TO
THE PRESSURE COOKER TOGETHER?
WE ADD WATER TO IT...
WHEN WE PRESSURE-COOK IT.
SO WE'VE GOT OUR OXTAIL
READY TO GO.
NOW WE HAVE TO STEW IT,
WHICH WE CALL "BROWN DOWN."
"BROWN DOWN"?
YEAH.
DOWN!
FIRST WE DO THE OIL,
THEN WE HAVE TO DO
THE SUGAR IN HERE.
WE GOT A LITTLE CARAMELIZATION
GOING ON? HENCE THE BROWN.
SEE THAT BEAUTIFUL
GOLDEN COLOR IT'S GETTING?
UH-HUH.
IT ALMOST LOOKS LIKE
IT'S BURNING.
ONE SECOND.
HOLD IT.
OKAY, AND THEN YOU
HAVE TO STEP BACK.
THERE WE GO.
(sizzling)
(whooshing)
YOU STOOD RIGHT IN THERE
LIKE A WARRIOR.
YOU HAVE TO.
ONIONS. GARLIC. CILANTRO.
KETCHUP?
ALLSPICE.
CARROTS. CABBAGE.
RED PEPPERS--
THE TRINITY COOKING
OF CARIBBEAN FOOD.
YOU WANT THAT VEGETABLES
TO BE NICE AND CRISP.
SO...
THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
GONNA SERVE THIS WITH
RED BEANS AND RICE.
LOOK AT THAT MEAT--
TENDER, FLAKY, PULL-APARTY.
SUPER-HOTTIE, SMOLDERY
BURNY-MOUTHY?
SKIN GRAFFY FIXY TOPPY ROOFY.
MMM. AH, THAT'S NICE.
IT'S SWEET. IT'S SAVORY.
MMM!
THE VEGETABLES HAVE
A NICE LITTLE CRUNCH.
THE RICE AND BEANS
GOES ALONG GREAT.
(mouth full) THIS GRAVY...
MMM!
IT'S SOFT AS BUTTER,
AND IT'S BEAUTIFUL,
AND I JUST WANNA
GO TO SLEEP IN IT.
MMM!
GET AWAY FROM ME.
STEW--OXTAILS WITH
RED BEANS AND RICE.
THIS FOOD IS RIDICULOUS.
VERY GOOD.
CARIBBEAN FOOD AT ITS BEST!
I SAY IT'S THE FIRST, THE LAST,
THE BEST, AND THE MOST!
IT'S RIGHT IN THE HEART
OF THE TWIN CITIES,
BUT THE FLAVOR'S
COAST-TO-COAST.
SOME OF THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU'RE AWESOME.
I WILL BE BACK.
UP NEXT...
(sizzling)
BIRD IS THE WORD.
CHICKEN BURGER,
SWEET FRIES.
WE'RE HEADED
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS...
ROLL.
WHERE A TINY CAFÉ...
HERE AT RAMBO CAFÉ...
IS BIG ON THE HANDMADE.
WANT SOME GRAVY?
THIS IS BODY BY GRAVY.
♪♪
I LOVE COMING DOWN
TO AUSTIN, TEXAS.
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE MUSIC,
THOSE CRAZY BATS THAT LIVE UNDER
CONGRESS STREET BRIDGE,
AND THEN, THE FOOD.
SO HERE WE ARE ON LAMAR STREET
TO CHECK OUT THIS HUGE JOINT--
I MEAN, WE'RE TALKIN'
700 SQUARE FEET--
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING UP
QUALITY COMFORT FOOD
TO A WHOPPING 26 SEATS.
THIS IS THE COUNTER CAFÉ.
GOOD MORNING, Y'ALL.
IT'S A SMALL, COZY,
COMFORTABLE DINER.
ORDER UP, PLEASE--
COUNTER BURGER, SPRING SALAD.
THEY'RE DOING THINGS FROM
SCRATCH RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
ORDER UP--
BISCUITS AND GRAVY.
OKAY, TOM, HERE YOU GO.
I JUST ENJOY DEBBIE'S COMPANY
EVERY MORNING.
AND EVERY AFTERNOON, 'CAUSE
NO MATTER WHEN YOU SHOW UP...
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
CHANCES ARE,
OWNER DEBBIE DAVIS
IS LIGHTING UP THE JOINT
WITH HER TEXAS CHARM.
ORDER UP, PLEASE--
BREAKFAST SANDWICH.
BUT SHE AIN'T RUNNIN'
THIS SHOW ALONE.
ORDER UP--
BLUEBERRY HOTCAKE.
THE CHEFS, NICK AND STEVE,
THE CRUZ BROTHERS,
ARE JUST FABULOUS.
DOESN'T GET ANY BETTER
THAN THOSE BROTHERS.
CHICKEN BURGER, SWEET FRIES.
IT'S LIKE
THE CHICKEN BURGER SUPREME.
IT'S GROUND CHICKEN AND ONIONS,
CURRY--IT'S YUMMY.
WE'RE GRINDING SOMETHING.
WE'RE GRINDING CHICKEN.
MAKE SOME CHICKEN BURGER.
AND DOING THE THIGH?
YEAH.
OKAY, SO LET ME JUST
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
TINY KITCHEN, TWO GUYS WORKING,
LOTS OF VOLUME--
BUY GROUND CHICKEN?
NO.
NOT THE WAY IT WORKS
AT THE COUNTER?
NO WAY.
YOU'VE GOT THE GRINDER.
ROLL.
(whirring)
I'M JUST TRYING NOT TO WEAR
THE CHICKEN BITS.
GRINDING SOME GARLIC.
A JALAPEÑO.
(whirring)
MINCED RED ONIONS.
OKAY.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
THEN ADD SOME YELLOW CURRY.
SALT. AND A LITTLE BIT
OF PEPPER.
IT'S LOCAL ORGANIC HONEY.
GONNA MIX THIS UP.
OKAY, SO THE FAT
IN THE CHICKEN
HELPS JUST TIE
EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
THAT KIND OF WORKS
AS THE BINDER ITSELF.
IT DOES. YEAH.
NOW THIS IS GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE TIME TO SET UP.
I'M GONNA PUT IT IN THE FRIDGE,
WE'RE GONNA KEEP IT OVERNIGHT.
OKAY.
CHICKEN BURGER ON?
CHICKEN BURGER ON.
(sizzling)
LET IT START TO CRUST UP
SO IT STAYS TOGETHER.
RIGHT.
(sizzling continues)
YOU A BIG SWEET POTATO FAN?
OH, YEAH. DEFINITELY.
(mouth full) THAT'S A TASTY FRY.
GOOD CRUNCH.
AND A WHEAT BUN.
CHICKEN BURGER.
WOW! I GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SPICE.
PROBABLY THE UNDERLYING TONE
OF THE WHOLE THING IS THE CURRY.
RIGHT.
MMM!
BUT IT'S SUPER MOIST.
I MEAN, JUICY AS CAN BE.
TENDER, GOOD BITE,
LOTS OF FLAVOR.
THE ONIONS, THE JALAPEÑOS,
THE GARLIC...
(mouth full) JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF HONEY. CAN'T BEAT IT.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
THANKS.
CHICKEN BURGER, SWEET FRIES.
AND IT'S 26 SEATS
AND 700 SQUARE FEET.
INCLUDING THE BATHROOMS,
700 SQUARE FEET.
WAY TO ADD THAT IN.
NOT A LOT OF PEOPLE
PUT THAT IN THEIR BROCHURE.
ADD THE BATHROOMS.
ORDER UP--
TWO BREAKFAST TACOS.
YOU'VE GOT TO BE
JUST WOWED.
JIMMIE VAUGHAN
SITTING AT THE COUNTER.
WELL, THIS IS WHERE YOU
COME FOR BREAKFAST.
MORNING. HERE'S YOUR
QUAIL AND EGGS.
QUAIL YOU DON'T GET EVERYWHERE,
SO IT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
TO COME HERE.
IT'S LIKE A BETTER CHICKEN.
BISCUITS--OUTSTANDING, TOO.
TELL ME WHAT WE'RE MAKING.
UH, WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME HOMEMADE BISCUITS
FROM SCRATCH--BUTTERMILK.
IF YOU DON'T MAKE
A SCRATCH-MADE BISCUIT HERE,
YOU PROBABLY GET
RUN OUT OF TOWN.
EXACTLY.
I SAW THAT POSTER.
OKAY, GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
UNBLEACHED
ORGANIC FLOUR HERE.
OF COURSE.
I'M GONNA ADD MY BAKING POWDER.
BAKING SODA. SUGAR.
SALT. GONNA ADD
MY BUTTER CUBES.
AND THAT'S SO WE DIVERSIFY
THE FAT THROUGHOUT THE BISCUIT
SO YOU GET THE FLAKINESS.
CORRECT.
MASH IT UP
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
BUT NOT ENOUGH THAT YOU
START TO BREAK IT DOWN.
IF YOU MELT THAT BUTTER, YOU
JUST DON'T GET THAT SEPARATION.
EXACTLY.
OKAY.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
MY BUTTERMILK.
MIXING THAT UP.
(clattering)
GONNA FLIP THIS BOWL OVER.
WE'LL GET IT
HAND-PATTIED OUT
AND START HITTING IT
WITH THE...
(makes whooshing sounds)
LINING 'EM UP.
ALL RIGHT.
400. HOW LONG?
ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
HOT AND FAST.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
DOING SOME QUAIL.
BIRD IS THE WORD.
MOST TIMES WHEN I COME TO TEXAS,
I CAN GET GOOD QUAIL.
GONNA GRILL SOME
ON THE GRILL RIGHT NOW.
SALT AND PEPPER IT.
(sizzling)
ALL RIGHT, SO THE BISCUITS
ARE DOWN.
THE QUAIL'S COOKING.
WHAT'S NEXT?
I JUST PULLED
MY POACHED EGGS.
NOTHING I LIKE MORE THAN
PULLING SOME POACHED EGGS.
MY FRESH BAKED BISCUITS.
TAKE THAT OUT.
IS THIS A STAPLE?
AT THE COUNTER?
YEAH.
OH, YEAH.
QUAIL AND EGGS.
(sizzling)
QUAIL, POACHED EGGS,
FRESH-MADE BISCUITS,
AND HASH BROWNS
THAT YOU CUT.
START PULLING APART.
MMM.
IT'S GOOD QUAIL.
NICE QUAIL, HUH?
(mouth full) WHAT DO YOU
SERVE WITH YOUR BISCUITS?
SOME GRAVY ON THERE.
LET'S GET DOWN
THE GRAVY, BABY.
WANT SOME GRAVY?
DO I WANT SOME GRAVY?
THIS IS BODY BY GRAVY.
MMM!
HERE'S WHAT I LIKE.
I'M NOT A HUGE BREAKFAST FAN,
BUT IF I'M GONNA EAT BREAKFAST,
I WANT TO HAVE HAND-MADE FOOD.
'CAUSE YOU'RE DOING
EVERYTHING FRESH,
YOU'RE MAKING
YOUR OWN BISCUITS.
EVERYTHING TIES TOGETHER
REALLY NICE.
(mouth full) I MEAN, IT IS--
IT'S ON POINT, MAN.
GOOD JOB, MAN.
THANK YOU.
HEY. THANK YOU.
ORDER UP, PLEASE--
QUAIL AND EGGS, SCRAMBLED.
IT'S A LITTLE RICHER,
FULLER QUALITY THAN CHICKEN.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
AND EVERYBODY LEAVES HAPPY
NO MATTER WHAT THEY ORDER.
AND SO RIGHT AFTER
LUNCH IS SERVED,
THERE'S A FLOOR SHOW
WITH NICK AND STEVE
AND DANCING AND PUPPETS?
ON THE COUNTER.
NOW I UNDERSTAND.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS
FLAVOR TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY!
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
WHAT DO YOU DO FOR WORK?
UH, A CRIMINAL
DEFENSE ATTORNEY.
SO YOU'LL BE ABLE TO GO
IN THE COURTROOM
WITH ALL THAT RED SAUCE
ON YOUR SHIRT RIGHT THERE?
DO I?
DID YOU SEE THAT?
(laughter)
JUST KIDDING. (laughs)
GOOD JOB.