HEY, THERE. I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
NO WAY!
YES!
IT'S VEGAS, BABY.
WHOA-STYLE.
OFF THE STRIP...
WE GOT ISSUES.
AND OUT OF CONTROL.
(laughing loudly)
SUICIDE FRIES ARE UP.
A HOLE-IN-THE-WALL BAR...
THIS IS GRANDMA'S SECRET.
HIDING A BUFFALO PIZZA JOINT.
"GET NAKED"--IS THAT
A THREAT OR A PROMISE?
OH, IT'S
A CONVERSATION STARTER.
THE BULGARIAN TAPAS SPOT--
THAT'S RIGHT, BULGARIAN...
IN VEGAS? I THOUGHT IT WAS ALL
STROMBOLI AND CHICKEN WINGS.
DISHING OUT
EUROPEAN COMFORT FOOD...
KUEF-TAY.
YEAH.
AND INTERNATIONAL DIPLOMACY.
AHH.
(speaking Bulgarian)
WE'RE HAVING
A LITTLE BIT
OF A CULTURAL INTERVENTION
RIGHT NOW.
NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO, NO.
PLUS A COLLEGE REUNION...
ARE YOU READY TO TAKE A TRIP
DOWN MEMORY LANE?
THAT DOESN'T DISAPPOINT
IN THE FLAVOR DEPARTMENT.
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE, SIX.
(all laughing)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
WHEW. I'M HERE IN
BUFFALO, NEW YORK, IN JANUARY.
ALL RIGHT, I CAN'T LIE.
I'M IN LAS VEGAS, AND I'M,
LIKE, ONLY, I DON'T KNOW,
A MILE AWAY FROM THE STRIP, BUT
I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE A FORMER CASINO
EXECUTIVE CHEF
IS GOING BACK
TO HIS BUFFALO ROOTS.
OH, HE'S KNOCKING OUT
THIS KILLER EAST COAST PIE,
EXCEPT HIS PLACE IS TUCKED AWAY
IN A BAR CALLED MOON DOGGIE'S.
THIS IS NAKED CITY PIZZA.
PEPPERONI PIZZA'S UP.
THE PIE IS TO DIE FOR.
(man) IT'S ALL HOME-MADE HERE,
YOU KNOW?
EVERYTHING IS GONNA BE FRESH
THE SECOND YOU ORDER IT.
(man) TO BE ABLE
TO COME TO A BAR
AND TO HAVE THIS QUALITY FOOD,
IT'S LIKE GOURMET
IN A NON-GOURMET SITUATION...
THANKS TO CHRIS PALMERI,
WHO DITCHED
THE COLD BUFFALO WINTERS
TO COOK AT THE MGM GRAND.
CHICKEN FINGER SUB,
TABLE ONE.
NOW HE'S BROUGHT
HIS EAST COAST FLAVOR
TO THE OLD NAKED CITY
NEIGHBORHOOD OF LAS VEGAS.
"GET NAKED"--IS THAT
A THREAT OR A PROMISE?
OH, IT'S
A CONVERSATION STARTER.
IT'S A PLACE HELPING BUFFALO
TRANSPLANTS FEEL RIGHT AT HOME.
WE COME HERE EVERY SUNDAY
WHEN THE BILLS ARE PLAYING.
MIGHT NOT GET A GOOD,
UH, BUFFALO BILLS GAME,
BUT WE'LL ALWAYS GET
A GOOD BITE TO EAT.
LIKE A SICILIAN-STYLE PIZZA
YOU'D FIND UPSTATE...
(woman)
THE GUINEA PIE.
TOPPED WITH FRESH RICOTTA
CHEESE AND HOMEMADE MEATBALLS.
THE BEST SLICE OF PIZZA
IN LAS VEGAS.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA GRIND THE MEAT UP
FOR OUR MEATBALLS.
MY GRANDMA'S RECIPE.
YOUR GRANDMA HAD A GRINDER
LIKE THIS AT HOME?
OH, SHE WAS A TOUGH OLD LADY.
SHE DID THE HAND CRANK.
REALLY?
HENCE THE FOREARMS,
I GUESS. OKAY.
EXACTLY.
WELL, WE GOT CHUCK,
AND WE GOT BRISKET.
OKAY.
WE DO A LITTLE BIT
HIGHER FAT CONTENT.
WE'RE DOING,
LIKE, A 70/30.
REALLY?
JUST GET OUR GRINDER GOING
AND START FEEDING 'EM THROUGH.
YOU'RE A SMALL, LITTLE PIZZA
JOINT IN A BAR IN VEGAS.
YOU CAN BUY
THE GROUND MEAT.
EVERYBODY BUYS
WE DON'T. WE DO
EVERYTHING FROM SCRATCH.
YOU DON'T.
ANY PIZZA THAT'S GOT MY NICKNAME
HAS GOT TO HAVE A LOT OF WORK.
YOUR NICKNAME
IS "GUINEA"?
YES, SIR.
I THOUGHT I GOT A TOUGH ONE
WHEN I GOT NICKNAMED "GUIDO."
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE UP OUR MEATBALLS.
HIT IT.
FIRST THING WE GOT
IS OUR WHITE ONIONS
AND OUR GARLIC
THAT WE SAUTéED...
OKAY.
ITALIAN PARSLEY,
FRESH MINT.
WHOA.
I'VE HAD THAT BEFORE,
BUT IN GREEK MEATBALLS.
THIS IS GRANDMA'S SECRET.
FRESH BASIL.
OH, IT SMELLS AWESOME.
FRESH BREADCRUMBS--
NOT A WHOLE LOT.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
TO BIND IT ALL TOGETHER.
PARMESAN CHEESE, KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER.
I LOVE YOUR MEASUREMENTS--
WHOA-STYLE!
THAT'S HOW GRANDMA
WROTE IT.
SHE JUST WROTE INGREDIENTS,
NO MEASUREMENTS.
DIG IT.
MIX IT UP.
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE IN
A FIGHT WITH IT.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT TO SHOW IT
WHO'S BOSS, YOU KNOW?
RIP OFF
A NICE PORTION OF IT.
CHUNK.
GONNA GET IT TOGETHER.
INTO THE OVEN
RUNNING AT, WHAT, 650?
650.
SEVEN, EIGHT MINUTES.
YES, SIR.
OUT OF THE OVEN.
THIS THING IS NOT
LIGHT ON THE FAT. OOH.
GOT A LITTLE KISS OF THE MINT.
TASTY MEATBALL.
GONNA SLICE IT INTO
ABOUT FOUR OR FIVE SLICES.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT TOGETHER OUR PIZZA.
WE GOT OUR DOUGH.
WE MAKE THIS TWICE A DAY.
WE LET IT SIT
OVERNIGHT TO RISE.
OKAY.
FLOUR IT, POUND IT OUT
ON THE TABLE, PINCH, AND PULL.
YOU BUILD A LITTLE CRUST
GOING AROUND THERE.
YEAH, IN BUFFALO, THEY DO
A FULL SHEET PIZZA.
WE WANTED TO STICK
WITH THE BUFFALO THING.
SO YOU CAN
GET IT ON THERE.
MAKES IT
NICE AND EASY.
PUT IT RIGHT THERE
ON THE MIDDLE, FOLD IT OVER.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT DOWN
OUR WHITE GARLIC SAUCE,
CHOPPED BABY SPINACH,
AND OUR CHOPPED MEATBALLS
THAT WE SLICED UP BEFORE.
WHOLE MILK
SHREDDED MOZZARELLA.
YOU GRATE YOUR OWN MOZZ,
AS WELL?
YES, WE DO.
BEAUTIFUL.
FINISH THIS WITH
OUR IN-HOUSE RICOTTA.
OKAY.
FINALLY, WE HIT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF DRIED OREGANO.
IN THE OVEN AT 650
HOW LONG?
ABOUT 7, 8 MINUTES.
BROWN ON TOP. THE CHEESE
IS CARAMELIZING UP NICE.
GONNA THROW IT BACK ON THE DECK,
THROW A LITTLE CRUST ON IT.
WE'RE GONNA
PULL IT OUT.
RIGHT DOWN HERE.
DELICIOUS.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO WE'RE GONNA GO
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
THERE WE GO.
BOOM. 12 SLICES.
HAVE AT IT.
HMM. VERY RICH,
VERY CREAMY.
GOOD SALT COMING
OUT OF THAT RICOTTA.
THE MEATBALLS ARE TASTY.
DELICIOUS.
THAT LITTLE BIT OF MINT WAS
REALLY REFRESHING AND DIFFERENT.
DUDE, AWESOME.
BUT IT WOULDN'T BE
A TRUE BUFFALO JOINT
WITHOUT SOME BLAZING HOT SAUCE.
I WOULDN'T SAY THAT ALL
FOOD'S SPICY IN BUFFALO,
BUT IT'S ALWAYS GOOD
TO HAVE SOMEONE
THAT KNOWS HOW TO MAKE
A GOOD HOT SAUCE.
AND CHRIS DEFINITELY BRINGS IT
WITH THIS 1/2 POUND
OF HEARTBURN.
SUICIDE FRIES.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
SOUTHWEST CUISINE MEETS HELL.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE GONNA DO OUR HOT PEPPER
MEDLEY FOR OUR SUICIDE FRIES.
THAT'S MY KIND OF NAME.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
SOME OLIVE OIL, CHERRY PEPPERS,
CHOPPED JALAPEÑO...
NICE.
PEPPERONCINIS,
AND SOME SERRANOS.
SO WE'RE GONNA SAUTé 'EM
AROUND A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT. GLAZE WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
KIND OF SWEAT
THE PEPPERS DOWN SOME.
SO THESE ARE FINISHED.
NOW WHAT DO WE DO?
SUICIDE SAUCE--A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL, HABANERO CHILI.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS
AND GARLIC.
GET THESE BROWNING UP.
THEN WE'RE GONNA DEGLAZE THE PAN
WITH SOME RED WINE VINEGAR.
IF YOU HAVE A SINUS ISSUE,
YOU'D BE CLEANED OUT HERE
IN ABOUT 30 SECONDS.
WE'RE GONNA SEASON WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF KOSHER SALT,
A LITTLE BIT
OF BLACK PEPPER,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF CHOPPED
ITALIAN PARSLEY FOR COLOR.
LOOKING AT A DEAD MAN.
IT'S GONNA BE
A LITTLE SPICY.
LAST PIECE IS GONNA BE
OUR FRANK'S RedHot SAUCE.
LET THIS SIMMER
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
BRING IT ALL TOGETHER
WITH
THE IMMERSION BLENDER.
(whirs slowly)
SEE, IT DOESN'T EVEN
LIKE BEING IN THERE.
NEXT, WE'RE GONNA
HAND-CUT OUR FRENCH FRIES.
TO ORDER?
TO ORDER.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA JUST
DROP 'EM IN THE FRYER,
AND WE'RE GONNA FRY 'EM OFF
FOR ABOUT THREE, FOUR MINUTES.
OKAY.
AND WE'RE GONNA PULL 'EM UP,
AND WE'RE GONNA LET 'EM REST
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE. THEN
WE'RE GONNA DROP 'EM AGAIN.
THE FIRST FRY COOKS 'EM
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
THEN YOU FRY 'EM AGAIN,
AND IT BROWNS THE OUTSIDE.
YEP.
JUST RIGHT INTO THE BOWL--
KOSHER SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF ITALIAN PARSLEY.
(Chris) SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
PILE 'EM ON OUR PLATE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
BUILDING OUR SUICIDE FRIES.
OUR HOT PEPPER BLEND
FROM BEFORE--
I'M JUST GONNA THROW THOSE
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THEN WE FINISH IT
WITH THAT SUICIDE SAUCE
THAT YOU LOVE SO MUCH
THAT CLEARS UP THE SINUSES.
JUST FOR FUN,
I GIVE YOU A LITTLE SIDE
OF THE HOUSE-MADE RANCH.
A LITTLE DEVIL NUGGET.
I'LL GIVE THAT
TO YOU.
WOW!
IT'S GOT SOME HEAT.
(laughs)
GOING TO WARM TOWN.
THE MEDLEY OF PEPPERS
IS AMAZING.
THE HOT SAUCE
IS DYNAMITE.
OKAY, THE HEAT'S
COMING IN NOW.
THIS IS
REAL-DEAL FOOD.
SUICIDE FRIES
ARE UP.
HOTTER THAN THE HOTTEST DAY
HERE IN LAS VEGAS.
(woman laughs)
(laughs) MMM.
THEY'RE TO DIE FOR.
BROTHER, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING--
ANYTHING YOU WOULD MAKE,
I WOULD PROBABLY BE A FAN OF.
YOU JUST HAVE SUCH PASSION
ABOUT IT. YOU TALK ABOUT IT.
I MEAN, YOU GRAB THE SALT
WITH ENTHUSIASM.
THE REAL DEAL. IF YOU'RE
IN VEGAS OR WITHIN 100 MILES,
COME CHECK THIS CAT OUT.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
WEST OF THE STRIP
TO A BULGARIAN SPOT...
YOU CAN'T FIND THIS FOOD
ANYPLACE ELSE IN THIS CITY.
SERVING UP EASTERN
EUROPEAN FLAVORS...
WHERE'S THIS BEEN
ALL MY DIET?
AND THROWING OUT
THE RULE BOOK...
(speaking Bulgarian)
OF INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS.
OH, THIS HAS JUST TURNED
INTO "MAURY POVICH."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I THINK BY NOW,
EVERYBODY KNOWS
THAT I WENT TO U.N.L.V.
I MEAN, I LOVE VEGAS. WE'RE
TALKING GREAT ENTERTAINMENT,
HOTELS, CASINOS,
AND THE FOOD, I MEAN,
YOU CAN FIND ALMOST
EVERY TYPE OF FOOD HERE,
BUT I WILL TELL YOU
AS A LITTLE SURPRISE
TO FIND OUT ON THE CORNER
OF FLAMINGO AND RAINBOW--
BULGARIAN FOOD?
OH, GET READY.
THIS IS FORTE.
YOU CAN'T FIND THIS FOOD
ANYPLACE ELSE IN THIS CITY.
(woman) IT'S LIKE YOU'RE NOT
IN LAS VEGAS.
IT'S LIKE YOU'RE--
YOU'RE IN EUROPE...
SPECIFICALLY BULGARIA,
WHERE NINA MANCHEV COMES FROM.
(speaking Bulgarian)
NINA IS A TOTAL POWERHOUSE.
WHAT ELSE WOULD YOU CALL
A 23 YEAR OLD
WHO OPENS HER OWN RESTAURANT
WHILE SHE'S GOING TO
MY ALMA MATER, U.N.L.V.?
HOW REAL-DEAL
IS THIS?
ABSOLUTELY REAL-DEAL.
IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
FLAVOR, THE SEASONINGS.
(woman) STUFFED PEPPER UP.
I LIKE THE SAUSAGES.
AND BULGARIANS KNOW
A THING OR TWO ABOUT SAUSAGE...
(woman) THE MIXED GRILL PLATE.
A DISH THAT'S LOADED
WITH THEM.
THERE'S THREE DIFFERENT
KINDS OF MEATS...
THAT ARE ALL HOMEMADE,
AS WELL.
UM, KNIFE OF
GREAT-GREAT-GRANDFATHER.
BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH, YEAH.
(man speaking Bulgarian)
(speaking Bulgarian)
WE'RE HAVING
A LITTLE BIT
OF A CULTURAL INTERVENTION
RIGHT NOW.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
(speaking Bulgarian)
WHAT HE'S
TELLING HER RIGHT NOW
IS DON'T SHARE
THE FAMILY RECIPE.
AAH.
NOW HE'S STORMING OFF,
AND, OH, THIS HAS JUST
TURNED INTO "MAURY POVICH."
WHO IS THAT?
(Nina) MY FATHER.
YOUR DAD?
MY FATHER.
(speaking Bulgarian)
OH, HE'S BACK.
HE'S BACK.
(speaking Bulgarian)
NOW NEIL, OUR P.A., JUMPS IN,
AND IT'S GONNA BE BATTLE ROYALE.
GO GET HIM, NEIL.
WHAT ARE YOU
ARGUING ABOUT?
(man shouting
in Bulgarian)
HE'S COMING BACK.
(speaking Bulgarian)
I TOLD THAT HE'S
GOING TO COOK, BUT...
(speaking Bulgarian)
YEAH, BUT WE'VE BEEN HERE
FOR ABOUT 20 YEARS,
SO, YOU KNOW, WE SPEAK
ENGLISH PRETTY WELL.
WHAT'S UP, MAN?
(laughing)
(laughs) NO WAY!
YES.
(laughing)
(laughing loudly)
YOU HAVE NO ACCENT?
I'M BACK HERE
LOOKING FOR SOME EGO.
THAT, MY FRIENDS,
IS HOW I GET PUNK'D
ON MY OWN SHOW.
LET'S JUST SAY
REVENGE WILL BE SWEET.
TODAY WE'RE GONNA BE MAKING
TWO DIFFERENT STYLES
OF THE BULGARIAN SAUSAGE,
WHICH ALL GO INTO
THE BULGARIAN
MIXED GRILL.
WE'RE GONNA BE DOING
KEBAPCHE AND KYUFTE.
THE THIRD ONE
WHICH IS LOUKANIKO,
THAT ONE IS CASED.
SO YOU'RE GONNA MAKE
TWO OF THE THREE.
FIRST, WE CUBE
EQUAL PARTS PORK--
PORK CUSHION,
AND PORK BUTT.
BOTH OF 'EM HAVE,
YOU KNOW, NICE FAT CONTENT.
NOW THAT WE HAVE ALL
OF OUR MEAT CUBED,
WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT.
FIRST, WE HAVE THE KEBAPCHE--
SALT, CUMIN.
THE ONLY THING THAT'S
REALLY SURPRISING TO ME
IS THE, UH, CUMIN.
A MAJORITY OF THE DIFFERENT
SAUSAGES AND CHARCUTERIE,
THEY'RE FLAVORED
WITH--WITH CUMIN.
"CHARCUTERIE"--YOU CAN GET
THAT WORD OUT. THAT'S AWESOME.
CHARCUTERIE.
SAVORY OR BULGARIAN OREGANO,
ESSENTIALLY.
OKAY.
VERY LIGHT
IN THE OREGANO FIELD.
YEAH.
FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
AND WHO TAUGHT YOU
TO DO ALL THIS?
IT'S BEEN PASSED DOWN
FROM GENERATION TO GENERATION,
UM, WHICH TAUGHT
MY FATHER.
SO IT REALLY HAS PASSED
THROUGH THE FAMILY.
ABSOLUTELY. NEXT,
WE ADD ALLSPICE, SUGAR.
OKAY, NEXT ONE IS...
THE KYUFTE IS THE ONE
THAT'S SHAPED LIKE A PATTY.
FIRST UP, THE CUMIN.
SAVORY--THE BULGARIAN SAVORY.
BLACK PEPPER.
OKAY.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
NEXT, THE SALT.
WE HAVE THE SUGAR, THYME,
JUST GROUND CORIANDER.
SO WE'RE GONNA
COVER EVERYTHING UP
AND PUT IT IN
THE COOLER OVERNIGHT.
LET'S GRIND SOME SAUSAGE.
AND JUST ONE GRIND?
JUST ONE GRIND.
SO WE'LL GRIND IT
THROUGH HERE.
THEN WE PUT IT
IN THE MIXER AFTER THAT?
CORRECT.
GOT TO SMEAR IT TOGETHER
TO GET IT MORE CONTACT.
YEAH, AND IT GETS IT TO
A REALLY STICKY CONSISTENCY.
IT MAKES IT
EASIER TO SHAPE.
OKAY.
WHICH ONE'S WHICH
AGAIN?
KYUFTE, KEBAPCHE.
OKAY, KYUFTE.
KUEF-TAY.
YEAH.
WE'RE GOING TO ADD
OUR GREEN ONION,
PARSLEY.
THEN WE JUST MIX
EVERYTHING TOGETHER
TO FORM IT
INTO A PATTY.
DOES IT GO ON
THE GRILL NOW, OR...
YEP.
OKAY, SO WHILE THAT ONE'S
COOKING, NEXT UP?
THE KEBAPCHE.
OKAY, THIS IS GONNA
BE THE FUN PART.
SO THIS ONE WE FORM
INTO A SAUSAGE,
AND THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
LIKE A PIECE
OF MEAT ROPE.
SO THIS ONE IS
THE LOUKANIKO.
IT'S SEMICURED
PORK SAUSAGE.
IT'S CURED
FOR ABOUT SIX DAYS.
IT HAS RED WINE, NUTMEG,
THE OREGANO IN IT.
THIS ACTUALLY DATES
BACK TO ROMAN TIMES.
AND THE ALLSPICE.
AND THIS IS MADE TO YOUR SPEC,
TO YOUR RECIPE.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO YOU SCORE IT
A LITTLE BIT.
TURN IT OVER,
FLATTEN IT OUT.
WE'RE ALMOST
A SALAMI THERE.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
A FLATTER PRODUCT.
OKAY.
AND WHAT'S ALL THIS
GONNA BE SERVED WITH?
LYUTENITSA, WHICH IS A ROASTED
RED PEPPER AND TOMATO SPREAD.
ALSO WITH BULGARIAN
BEAN RELISH
AND SOME ONIONS
AND PARSLEY.
THAT IS A PLATTER. GOT TO BE
CLOSE TO A POUND OF MEAT.
DIP IT IN THE LYUTENITSA.
THIS IS A TRADITIONAL WAY.
YOU CAN EVEN PICK UP
THE ONIONS WITH IT.
GREAT FLAVOR.
WHERE'S THIS BEEN
ALL MY DIET?
(laughs)
THE RIGHT BLEND OF SEASONINGS--
VERY RICH.
MM-HMM.
EACH ONE HAS ITS OWN
RESPECTIVE DIFFERENT TASTE,
AND THEN YOU DIP
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS, UH...
LYUTENITSA.
WHAT'S IN THE MIX?
TOMATO AND ROASTED PEPPER
SPREAD.
MMM. EASTERN EUROPE
COMFORT FOOD.
MMM.
AWESOME.
THIS RESTAURANT
REALLY REPRESENTS NINA.
THE ARTWORK, EVERYTHING
SHE'S DONE HERSELF.
IT'S VERY ECLECTIC, SO IT'S
COLORFUL, IT'S BRIGHT.
THERE'S A LOT OF HISTORY.
SAME GOES FOR THE MENU.
UP NEXT...
THRACIAN CLAY POT.
THE WHO-Y?
THAT'S BOUNTIFUL.
LOOK AT THIS.
DO YOU KNOW THAT AFTER
YOU EAT THE WHOLE THING,
YOU GET TO KEEP
THE POT?
DO YOU?
NOPE, JUST KIDDING.
SEE YOU LATER.
(laughing)
AT FORTE EUROPEAN TAPAS BAR
& BISTRO IN LAS VEGAS,
NINA MANCHEV DIDN'T
WASTE ANY TIME
GOING FROM COLLEGE STUDENT
TO SMALL BUSINESS OWNER.
SHE JUST HAD THIS DREAM,
AND UNLIKE A LOT OF PEOPLE,
SHE MADE IT COME TRUE.
SO YOU WERE GOING TO SCHOOL
WHILE YOU OPENED THIS?
YES.
I REALLY WANTED TO BRING
SOMETHING TO THE VEGAS COMMUNITY
THAT I THOUGHT
WAS LACKING.
WHAT WE DO HERE IS NOT
JUST EASTERN EUROPEAN.
IT GOES FROM SPAIN
TO BULGARIA
TO SERBIA TO RUSSIA...
EVEN THRACE.
THE THRACIANS WERE THE PEOPLE
WHO PRETTY MUCH CREATED
THE BUILDING BLOCKS
OF BULGARIAN CULTURE.
OKAY.
THIS ORIGINATED AROUND
THE FOURTH AND FIFTH CENTURY.
(Nina) THRACIAN CLAY POTS
ARE UP.
WE START WITH TOMATO.
AND NEXT, WE ADD OUR
ROASTED BELL PEPPERS.
ANY TYPE OF PEPPER, OR...
I LIKE USING, YOU KNOW,
THE RED OR THE YELLOW ONES
JUST FOR THE COLOR
AND SPICES.
AND THIS IS
THE BULGARIAN FETA?
YES.
AND THEN WE ADD
THE GREEN ONION,
AND THEN
WE ADD THE FETA CHEESE.
NEXT, WE ADD JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SAVORY BULGARIAN OREGANO,
AND JUST TOP IT OFF
WITH OLIVE OIL.
GREEK FEELING
TO IT HERE.
A LOT OF GREEK INFLUENCE
IN BULGARIAN FOOD.
ANOTHER TOMATO
ON TOP.
PUSH IT DOWN.
THIS BAKES FOR ABOUT
25 MINUTES.
AND NOW WE POT.
YEAH, DON'T TOUCH IT.
IT'S REALLY HOT.
THIS IS OUR LUKANKA.
THIS IS THE BULGARIAN
DRY-CURED CHARCUTERIE.
IT'S BEEN PRESSED, AND A LOT
OF THE FLAVOR'S JUST COMPACTED,
AND WE CUT THIS
EXTREMELY THIN.
THAT IS KILLER.
LIKE IT? GOOD.
IT'S A COMBINATION
OF PORK AND BEEF.
ARE YOU REALLY GONNA
PUT ALL THIS IN THERE?
MAJORITY OF IT.
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW MUCH
YOU WERE GONNA EAT,
SO I JUST KEPT CUTTING.
YEAH. I WOULD HAVE BEEN
WORRIED ABOUT THAT, TOO.
JUST STACK EVERYTHING.
HEALTHY LITTLE POT.
PUT OUR EGG, AND WE JUST
TAKE OUR SERRANO PEPPER.
WE DON'T TAKE THE SEEDS OUT
OR ANYTHING. THAT'S IT.
THIS NEEDS TO GO IN THE OVEN
FOR ANOTHER FIVE MINUTES.
THE MEAT CAN COOK AND THE PEPPER
CAN COOK AND THE EGG.
I DON'T KNOW WHEN
THE CLAY POT'S GONNA BE DONE,
BUT I'VE EATEN ABOUT 4 POUNDS
OF THIS KILLER...
LUKANKA.
EXACTLY. ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET IT.
IT'S REALLY,
REALLY HOT.
LET ME GUESS--
PAPRIKA.
CORRECT.
TRADITIONALLY, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE
MIX EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
IT'S VERY GOOD
TO DIP WITH BREAD.
YOU CAN PUT IT ON BREAD.
THIS IS CALLED A LEPINJA.
IT'S A TRADITIONAL
EASTERN EUROPEAN BREAD
THAT WE ALSO MAKE
IN-HOUSE.
WOW.
IT'S A VERY HEARTY DISH.
THAT'S BOUNTIFUL.
LOOK AT THIS.
YEP.
THERE'S FAR MORE THERE
THAN THE AVERAGE PERSON
CAN PROBABLY EAT.
(laughs)
WHEN I HEARD THAT THERE WAS
A PLACE SERVING BULGARIAN FOOD,
I HAD TO TRY IT.
FOOD'S GREAT. YOU'RE AMAZING.
THANK YOU.
YOU GOT TO CHECK IT OUT,
REALLY.
IN VEGAS? I THOUGHT IT WAS ALL
STROMBOLI AND CHICKEN WINGS.
YOU KNOW, COMING TO VEGAS,
EATING GREAT FOOD
MAKES ME A LITTLE HOMESICK--
A LITTLE HOMESICK
FOR MY ALMA MATER.
YOU KNOW WHAT TIME IT IS?
IT'S TIME FOR A U.N.L.V. FLYBY.
COMING UP...
I DON'T REMEMBER
THE BLING.
HE HAD A--KIND OF
A DIFFERENT HAIRSTYLE.
I'M HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL.
I CALL IT
A MODIFIED MULLET.
TO SEE WHAT THEY'RE COOKING UP
AT MY ALMA MATER.
I WENT TO SCHOOL
WITH THIS GUY. AWESOME.
YEAH.
♪♪
(laughs) THIS IS WHERE
IT ALL STARTED--U.N.L.V.
PROFESSOR EADE.
GUY.
NOW JUST SO YOU KNOW,
THIS IS THE GUY THAT
GOT ME THROUGH ALL OF IT.
PROFESSOR EADE WAS
MY COUNSELOR, MY ADVISOR
WHEN I WENT TO U.N.L.V.
(Vince) THERE ARE CERTAIN
STUDENTS WHO STAND OUT.
GUY HAD THAT REBEL SPIRIT.
ARE YOU READY TO TAKE A TRIP
DOWN MEMORY LANE?
THIS ISN'T THE SAME BUILDING,
BUT THIS HOUSES 367,
OR NOW IT'S CALLED
467?
467.
OH, HELP ME.
COMING IN.
(Vince) CHEF GREMO.
YES, SIR, VINCE.
WHAT'S UP, BROTHER?
HOW YOU DOING, MAN?
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
GOOD. NICE TO
SEE YOU AGAIN.
THIS IS WHO'S
IN CHARGE NOW?
WHAT CAN I SAY?
I WENT TO SCHOOL
WITH THIS GUY.
YEP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
IN HERE?
IS THIS JUST LIKE THE 367 CLASS
WAS ACROSS THE WAY?
YES, BUT I'M RUNNING
A RESTAURANT
ON THURSDAYS
AND FRIDAYS HERE.
THE KIDS RUN FRONT OF THE HOUSE
AND BACK OF THE HOUSE
JUST LIKE WE DID.
OKAY, SO THIS IS RECIPE TESTING.
DEVELOP THE RECIPES HERE...
YEP. YEP. YEP.
AND THEN IT GETS SERVED
OUT THERE IN THE RESTAURANT.
THAT'S CORRECT.
JUST LIKE WE DID,
BUT NOW THEY JUST ADDED
AN EXTRA HUNDRED ON IT.
YEAH, AND I'M TEACHING IT RIGHT,
THOUGH, YOU KNOW?
DIG IT.
GUY, I'VE GOT TO RUN.
I'VE GOT TO GO BACK TO CLASS.
THANKS. UH, ARE YOU GUYS
DOING A RECIPE RIGHT NOW?
YEAH. STUDENTS,
COME ON OVER, GUYS.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
HEY, GUYS.
(Chef Gremo) OKAY.
IF CHEF IS NOT TREATING YOU
NICE, YOU JUST LET ME KNOW,
'CAUSE I GOT
SOME PICTURES OF HIM.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
OKAY, WE'RE DOING
A LITTLE THAI SHRIMP SAUTé
WITH STICKY RICE
IN THE MIDDLE.
WHAT WE HAVE HERE
IS A U/10 P&D SHRIMP.
P&D IS PEELED
AND DEVEINED.
I DO A LITTLE BIT OF A CROSS
OF A DRY AND A WET RUB.
HIT IT.
OKAY. WE HAVE A LITTLE
LAS CRUCES RUB.
WE GOT A CHILI PEPPER
MEDLEY.
YEAH, MEDLEY,
EXACTLY.
OKAY.
YEAH, IT'S
REALLY GOOD.
THEN RIGHT HERE, I JUST GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF FLORIDA BAY,
A LITTLE TURMERIC,
CELERY SALT THERE,
CHIVE, A LITTLE PARSLEY,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT
OF SHALLOTS
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL.
A LITTLE BIT OF S AND P,
SALT AND PEPPER. MIX IT ALL UP.
AND HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA GO?
NOT MORE
THAN A HALF-HOUR.
SAUTé IT UP.
PAN'S HOT?
PAN'S HOT. I ADD
A LITTLE "CANOLER" ON THIS,
BECAUSE OLIVE OIL
TENDS--
DOES "CANOLA"
HAVE AN "R" IN IT?
CANOLA.
"CANOLER"?
(laughing)
OKAY, WHAT I'M GONNA DO IS JUST
ADD 'EM RIGHT IN. NICE AND HOT.
(sizzling)
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
LOOKING FOR--THE SIZZLE.
TOUCH OF WHITE WINE JUST TO GIVE
IT A LITTLE SWEETNESS, OKAY?
THAI SWEET CHILI
AGAIN.
NICE AND TIGHT.
OKAY, SHRIMP IS DONE.
GONNA PLATE IT UP--
STICKY RICE AND SLAW.
A LITTLE SAUCE
ON EACH.
PUT JUST A LITTLE CHIVE ON TOP,
A LITTLE GREEN ONION,
A LITTLE DAIKON RADISH
TO TOP IT OFF.
THAT'S OUR, UH,
SPICY THAI SHRIMP AND SLAW.
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE, SIX.
(laughing)
OH, CHEF, NONE
FOR YOU THIS TIME.
OH, NONE FOR ME.
IT'S OKAY.
YEAH.
GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT SLAW,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT RICE.
AWESOME. IT'S NOT
FLOATING IN THE SAUCE.
THE SHRIMP
IS COOKED PERFECTLY.
IT JUST KIND OF POPS A LITTLE
BIT WHEN YOU BITE ON IT.
YOU GET THAT CRUNCHINESS. YOU
GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT SOUR.
YOU GET SOME OF THAT
VINEGAR COMING THROUGH,
AND THEN RIGHT AFTER THAT, YOU
GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT SWEET
AND THAT GARLIC--THIS WHOLE
BALANCE THAT'S COMING THROUGH.
I'M TELLING YOU,
YOU CAN COME HERE,
GET THAT KIND OF FOOD
OUT OF THE 467 CLASS.
$7.
COME DOWN TO
THE NONPROFIT PROGRAM
HERE AT, UH,
HARRAH'S CULINARY COLLEGE.
(laughs) YEP. YEAH.
AWESOME. THANKS FOR
LETTING ME IN THE KITCHEN.
CHEF, IT'S A PLEASURE.
ALL RIGHT, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
I LOVE TO SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON AT U.N.L.V.
UH-HUH.
I LOVE TO SEE THAT
THE CULINARY ATTITUDE
IS CONTINUING
TO GO FORWARD STRONG.
NEXT, IT'LL BE YOU GUYS
TO CARRY IT ON.
THANK YOU.
SEE YOU GUYS. THANKS, MAN.
SEE YOU, BROTHER.
THANKS, GUY.
CERTAIN STUDENTS HAVE
AN "X" FACTOR--THAT WAS GUY.
I'M SO PROUD OF HIM. HARD
TO BELIEVE, BUT HE HAS MATURED.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT WEEK
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
JUST TAKE A LOOK.
JUST PAN AROUND HERE.
(laughing)
DEAD MAN. DEAD MAN.
ALREADY A DEAD MAN.
MORE DEAD, 'CAUSE YOU HAD
A CHANCE TO HELP ME OUT.
(laughing)
THAT'S ALL
FUN AND GAMES.