HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
YOU BETTER KEEP
THIS DOOR LOCKED.
BEARS AROUND HERE.
WE'RE HOOKIN' UP THE CAMARO
TO A SMOKER...
HOLY MOLY.
AND DOING A BARBECUE SHOW.
OH, MY GOD, THAT'S GOOD!
IN DALLAS, TEXAS...
SERVE IT UP, SAILOR.
THE REAL-DEAL BARBECUE JOINT...
IT IS SMOKE-RIDDLED,
"GNARLIFIED." WOW.
FOUND IN THE MOST UNLIKELIEST
OF PLACES.
"HEY, LET'S GO OPEN UP
A RESTAURANT,
BUT IN A FARMERS MARKET."
IT WAS ACTUALLY
OUR EXIT STRATEGY.
AND IN LAS VEGAS, NEVADA...
BRING IT!
THE 70-YEAR-OLD
BUTCHER SHOP...
IT STARTED OUT
IN BUTCHERING,
AND IT TURNED INTO...
EVERYTHING.
BLOWIN' UP THE BACKYARD 'CUE.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE
ONE OF THE BEST.
NOT JUST ON TRIPLE "D."
I'M TALKING IN GENERAL.
I GOT SOMETHING RIGHT HERE
ON THE SIDE OF MY MOUTH?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I LOVE FARMERS MARKETS.
I MEAN, THE BIG ONES,
THE LITTLE ONES,
IN THE COUNTRY, IN THE CITY--
I MEAN, I DON'T CARE
WHERE IT IS.
BUT I'M IN DALLAS,
AND I'M AT THIS FARMERS MARKET
THAT'S OVER 70 YEARS OLD.
NOW THEY GOT
ALL THE USUAL SUSPECTS--
HANDMADE GOODS, FRESH PRODUCE,
YOU NAME IT.
BUT I HEAR THERE'S
ONE EXTRA KEY--
BOMB BARBECUE BRISKET.
THIS IS THE PECAN LODGE
AT THE SHED 2.
(man) BRISKET, RIBS,
FRIED OKRA.
THESE GUYS
ROCK THE BRISKET?
THEY ROCK THE BRISKET.
I ADORE THE FRIED CHICKEN.
THEY DO BURNT ENDS
BETTER THAN ANYTHING
I'VE HAD IN KANSAS CITY.
(woman) OHH.
FIGHTIN' WORDS.
THEM IS
TWO BRISKET TACOS!
HOW'S THIS BARBECUE COMPARE?
I THINK IT'S ONE OF
THE BEST IN THE STATE.
THAT'S SAYING SOMETHING
IN A PLACE WHERE THERE'S
BARBECUES
ON JUST ABOUT
EVERY STREET CORNER.
AND THANKS TO JUSTIN
AND DIANE FOURTON...
BARBECUED BRISKET, HOT MESS,
BURNT ENDS, BANANA PUDDING.
FOLKS IN DALLAS CAN GET IT
IN THE SAME PLACE
THEY GO FOR FRESH PRODUCE.
AND WHO GETS THE WILD HAIR
THAT SAYS,
"HEY, LET'S GO OPEN UP
A RESTAURANT,
BUT IN A FARMERS MARKET"?
IT WAS ACTUALLY
OUR EXIT STRATEGY
OUT OF CORPORATE AMERICA.
TWO YEARS LATER, THESE
FORMER MANAGEMENT CONSULTANTS
HAVE 'EM LINING UP
FOR HOUSE-MADE SAUSAGE,
BEEF BURNT ENDS,
AND THE MAIN ATTRACTION--
WEST TEXAS BRISKET
WITH A SIDE OF EAST TEXAS
SAUCE.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
BARBECUE SAUCE.
A LITTLE OIL, GARLIC.
GOOD START.
ONION. GUAJILLO--
GUAJILLOS.
GUAJILLO PEPPERS.
MY FAVORITE PEPPER.
BASICALLY COOK THAT DOWN
SO IT BROWNS REALLY GOOD.
SALT. BLACK PEPPER.
'POTLE POWDER.
'POTLE. OKAY.
BROWN SUGAR.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
WHOOSH-OOSH-OOSH-SHIRE.
SOY.
THIS IS A CORNUCOPIA.
A LITTLE BIT OF MUSTARD.
KETCHUP. THAT'S
WHERE YOU GET YOUR SWEET.
HOW LONG ARE WE GONNA
LET THIS COOK DOWN?
ABOUT AN HOUR.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUREE IT?
YEP.
THEN IT'LL BE GOOD TO GO?
ALL RIGHT.
(whirs)
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NEXT,
BRISKET?
BRISKET.
THIS IS THE STATE BIRD
OF TEXAS, ISN'T IT?
IT IS.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE RUB.
WHAT ARE WE PUTTING ON IT?
LAWRY'S SEASONING SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
CHILI POWDER,
COARSE GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
MUSTARD POWDER, AND PAPRIKA.
OKAY.
WE'LL TAKE THIS
AND WHISK IT TOGETHER.
I LIKE THE BALANCE OF IT.
NOT TOO PEPPERY.
I LIKE A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
MUSTARD IN THERE.
OKAY. ON TO THE MEAT.
I TRY TO TRIM IT DOWN TO
ABOUT A QUARTER OF AN INCH.
YOU WANT TO LEAVE
MOST OF THE FAT ON.
IT HELPS TO KIND OF INSULATE IT
WHEN IT'S COOKING.
OKAY.
SO THAT'S PRETTY MUCH IT
WITH THE TRIMMING.
GET IT ON BOTH SIDES.
WE RUB IT DOWN, AND IT GOES
STRAIGHT ON THE SMOKER.
ONTO THE SMOKER?
YEP.
COOL.
GOING INTO THE LITTLE
MINI SHED.
OH, MAN!
LOOK AT THIS THING!
IT IS SMOKE-RIDDLED,
"GNARLIFIED."
KIND OF WOOD ARE YOU USING,
MESQUITE?
MESQUITE.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
250?
YEP.
AND THIS'LL COOK
FOR HOW LONG?
PROBABLY 15, 18 HOURS.
JEEZ.
(lid closes and opens)
(mouth full) OKAY.
LET'S GO EAT.
SERVE IT UP, SAILOR.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S DO IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
LITTLE BIT RIGHT THERE.
JUST PULLS APART.
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING, DUDE.
YOU REALLY--
YOU HIT THE SMOKE
ON THAT.
AND THIS IS THE BARBECUE
SAUCE WE MADE?
ALWAYS ON THE SIDE.
YOU SHOULD RENT COTS.
SOMEONE COMES DOWN
AND EATS THIS,
THEN THEY CAN JUST PASS OUT.
(chuckles) DUDE!
THIS IS CRAZY.
MMM.
YOU'RE A PRO, DUDE.
LISTEN.
I GO TO HAWAII,
I BETTER GET GREAT SUSHI.
(mouth full) I GO DOWN
TO CALIFORNIA,
I BETTER FIND SOME
BOMB MEXICAN FOOD.
WHAT YOU SHOULD BE FINDING
WHEN YOU COME TO TEXAS
IS ROCKIN' BRISKET.
THAT'S ROCKIN' BRISKET.
NICE JOB. AHH!
TAKE THAT AWAY... WITH ME.
BRISKET'S THE BOMB?
DUDE, THE BRISKET
IS RIDICULOUS.
YOU CAN SEE THE RED LINE
IN THERE
THAT'S SHOWING YOU HOW DEEP
THAT SMOKE'S GETTING IN THERE.
BUT IF YOU WANNA TRY
SOME OF THIS BARBECUE,
YOU BETTER HURRY...
YOU HAVE TO GET HERE EARLY.
ABSOLUTELY.
'CAUSE THEY'RE ONLY OPEN
16 HOURS A WEEK.
WE'RE OPEN THURSDAY
THROUGH SUNDAY FOR LUNCH.
FOR LUNCH?
MM-HMM.
NO WONDER YOU HAVE
SUCH A BIG SMILE.
WE START WEDNESDAY MORNING,
AND IT RUNS
24 HOURS A DAY UNTIL
WE CLOSE ON SUNDAY.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT FROM
THE MAN? HE'S ONLY HUMAN.
BESIDES SOME MORE 'CUE,
OF COURSE--
LIKE THIS SLOW-SMOKED
PORK SANDWICH
WITH A CAROLINA KICK.
IT'S GOT A REALLY GOOD
ZING TO IT.
ARE YOU ALLOWED TO DO
PORK IN TEXAS?
WE DO IT ANYWAY.
REALLY? 'CAUSE YOU
LIVE ON THE EDGE?
YEAH.
THIS IS A KIND OF A BLEND
OF THE CAROLINA STYLE SAUCES.
IT'S A VINEGAR-BASED SAUCE.
THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF MUSTARD IN IT.
OKAY.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR,
BROWN SUGAR,
BLACK PEPPER, CAYENNE PEPPER,
RED PEPPER, GARLIC POWDER.
YOU SAY IT WITH SO MUCH
ENTHUSIASM.
SALT.
MM-HMM.
WE HAVEN'T GOTTEN
TO THE PORK PART YET.
REALLY?
YEAH.
IS THAT WHEN YOU GET WILD?
YEAH. PORK RUB.
WHOSE PORK RUB?
MY PORK RUB.
OKAY. (laughs)
YOU SURE SAID THAT
WITH A BIG OL' GRIN.
YELLOW MUSTARD.
AND?
THIS ISN'T GONNA
COME OUT RIGHT.
HONET.
HONEY.
OKAY.
WHISK IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
COOK IT DOWN?
FOR 45 MINUTES
SO SOME OF THE VINEGAR
BURNS OFF.
COULD BE A LITTLE BIT SHARP
RIGHT NOW, BUT--
THAT'S GOOD.
THANKS.
OKAY. NEXT UP?
PORK RUB.
OKAY.
LAWRY'S,
BROWN SUGAR, SALT,
PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GOOD CALL.
THANKS. BLACK PEPPER,
GINGER.
NICE ON THE GINGER.
CUMIN.
AND MUSTARD.
MUSTARD.
SO BONELESS PORK BUTT?
BONELESS PORK BUTT.
REALLY HEAVY ALL OVER
THE OUTSIDE.
WE STILL GOT A FAT CAP
ON THERE?
YEP.
♪♪♪
AND THIS'LL GO ON
FOR HOW MANY HOURS?
12 TO 15 HOURS,
AT ABOUT 225.
HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT. ALL THE PORK BUTT'S
PULLED TO ORDER.
I ALWAYS TRY TO GET A--
NICE LITTLE MIX
OF BARK AND INTERIOR?
A NICE MIX OF BARK,
A LITTLE INTERIOR.
IT'S LIKE I READ YOUR MIND.
GOT A LOT OF FLAVOR.
I LIKE TO COME BACK
WITH A LITTLE BIT MORE.
MORE RUB?
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
NOW HOLD IT.
AND IT MELTS IN,
ALL RIGHT?
OKAY.
MEAT ON THE BUN.
ALL OF THAT?
ALL OF THAT.
A LITTLE PICKLE AND ONION,
SAUCE IF YOU WANT IT.
NICE, BEAUTIFUL, MOIST,
TENDER,
DRY-RUBBED, SMOKED
FOR MULTIPLE WEEKS.
(mouth full) AND THE SAUCE?
I COULDN'T CHANGE A THING, MAN.
MMM.
THAT'S LEGIT BARBECUE.
THANKS.
I MEAN, YOU'RE NOT
SCREWING AROUND.
NO.
YOU ARE THE REAL DEAL.
OUTSTANDING.
THANKS, MAN.
MMM! MMM, MMM, MMM!
OH, MY GOD, THAT'S GOOD!
♪♪♪
WELL, I GOTTA TELL YOU,
JUSTIN--
BOMB BRISKET, BOMB PORK.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK...
AND THIS HEALTHY COOKING HOUR
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BUTTER.
I'M GETTING A TASTE OF
THE SWEETER SIDE OF BARBECUE.
IT'S THE HOT MESS.
SO THAT'S THE TICKET?
YEAH.
WHO AM I COOKING WITH?
(Justin) THE BOSS LADY.
"BOSS LADY"? I'M SCARED.
YOU SHOULD BE.
♪♪♪
WELCOME BACK. WE'RE AT
THE DALLAS FARMERS MARKET,
TRIPLE "D," AND WE'RE
HANGING OUT AT THE PECAN LODGE
WITH THE BOSS LADY, AND GUESS
WHAT WE'RE MAKING UP NEXT?
THE HOT MESS.
A HOT MESS, MAC AND CHEESE.
DID YOU COME UP
WITH THAT NAME ON YOUR OWN?
IS THAT A SOUTHERN THING
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT?
IT IS A SOUTHERN THING.
IT IS A SOUTHERN THING?
MM-HMM.
THAT'S A BIG
SWEET POTATO.
IT IS A GIANT SWEET POTATO.
YOU'VE MOISTENED THEM.
WE HAVE.
WE'RE GOING TO...
LIBERALLY COAT THEM
WITH SOME SALT.
THOROUGHLY.
AND NOW IT JUST GOES
IN THE OVEN.
OKAY, HOW LONG?
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
THE BARBACOA.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
THE ADOBO SAUCE.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR OWN ADOBO?
YEAH.
WE'VE GOT OUR CHILIES.
WHAT TYPE OF CHILIES?
GUAJILLO.
ROUGH CHOP
A LITTLE ONIONS.
OKAY.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
SMOKED PAPRIKA.
A LITTLE ALLSPICE.
CUMIN. BLACK PEPPER.
SALT.
THERE'S NOT MUCH LEFT
IN THE PANTRY
THAT WE HAVEN'T
PUT IN THIS.
OREGANO.
YOU GUYS LIVE ON THE EDGE.
YEAH.
LIME JUICE.
AND SOME GARLIC CLOVES.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN STOCK
TO THIS,
JUST TO GET IT GOING.
GET THE JUICES GOING.
GOT A LITTLE JANIS JOPLIN
THING GOING ON OVER HERE.
A LOVE JANIS JOPLIN.
(whirring)
WE'RE JUST GONNA BLEND IT UP
SO THAT IT GETS PRETTY SMOOTH.
(whirring stops)
OKAY.
WE ARE GOING TO POUR IT OVER
THE BRISKET.
(smacking lips)
NICE SAUCE.
THANKS.
REALLY NICE SAUCE.
I GOTTA MASSAGE IT
A LITTLE FIRST.
DO YOUR MAGIC.
WE'RE GONNA ADD BAY LEAF.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
SO WE DON'T BURN
ON THE BOTTOM.
YEAH.
COVER WITH SOME FOIL,
IN THE OVEN.
350 DEGREES,
4 TO 5 HOURS?
YEAH.
BRING IT OUT, TAKE OFF
THE FAT, SHRED IT?
THAT'S RIGHT. CHILI POWDER,
CUMIN, SALT, AND THE ALLSPICE.
HOT MESS.
FIRST THING WE DO IS WE JUST
SPLIT IT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
OKAY.
SEE THAT NICE COLOR?
AND SHOVE SOME BUTTER
DOWN IN HERE.
AND THIS HEALTHY COOKING HOUR
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BUTTER.
(laughs)
AND A LITTLE CHEESE.
WE'RE GONNA ADD...
THE SHREDDED BRISKET.
BARBACOA, YES.
SOME CHIPOTLE CREAM.
AND... NOW...
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE
CRUMPLED BACON.
CHOPPED GREEN ONIONS,
JUST FOR COLOR.
IT'S ALL THE THINGS
YOU LOVE.
I'M NOT A SWEET POTATO FAN
IN THE SENSE OF...
YEAH.
SWEET POTATO CASSEROLE.
NOR AM I.
BUT THAT HAS THE SWEET
WITH THE SALTY
WITH THE TANG
OF THE BARBACOA.
RIGHT?
IT'S A COMPLETE MEAL.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
HOT MESS!
IF YOU'RE NOT HERE
BEFORE 11:30,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET ONE.
REALLY?
IT'S LIKE THEY CAN'T
MAKE ENOUGH OF THEM.
ONCE IN YOUR LIFETIME,
YOU HAVE TO TRY IT.
IT'S THE MESS.
THAT'S THE TICKET?
YEAH.
YOU KNOW, AND TOO MANY PEOPLE
SAY THEY CAN DO BARBECUE,
BUT I'M TELLING YOU,
REAL-DEAL, LEGIT.
GREAT FLAVORS, GREAT
SEASONING, GREAT SAUCE--
I MEAN, JUST REALLY
STANDUP-QUALITY BARBECUE,
AND IN TOUGH COMPANY,
BEING HERE IN DALLAS.
YEP.
SO... BEEN A PLEASURE.
UP NEXT...
(snaps fingers twice)
LOOK AT THAT
SAUSAGE-MAKING MONSTER.
WE'RE HEADED TO LAS VEGAS,
NEVADA...
NO, I WAS TALKING
ABOUT YOU.
(laughing)
WHERE A THIRD-GENERATION
BUTCHER SHOP
TURNED THE TABLES...
I LIKE YOUR HOOK,
CAPTAIN.
THIS IS A "COME HERE" HOOK.
AND STARTED DEALING
RIGHTEOUS BARBECUE.
YOU ARE DOING
COMPETITION-LEVEL MEAT.
♪♪♪
(bird calling)
NOW I'LL GIVE YOU
A LITTLE BIT OF HISTORY.
YOU KNOW, I WORKED
IN SOME BUTCHER SHOPS.
WHEN I WAS 12
GROWING UP IN FERNDALE,
I WORKED AT FERNDALE MEATS
MAKING THE JERKY.
WHEN I MOVED HERE TO LAS VEGAS
TO GO TO COLLEGE,
I WORKED AT SCHULMAN'S MEATS.
SO WHEN I FIND OUT THERE'S
A 70-YEAR-OLD BUTCHER SHOP
UP HERE IN NORTHWEST LAS VEGAS
THAT'S MAKING
THEIR OWN SAUCE, THEIR OWN RUBS,
THEIR OWN JERKY,
THEIR OWN SAUSAGE,
THEIR OWN BARBECUE,
AND THEY'RE SERVING IT
IN THEIR OWN BACKYARD,
I JUST GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS JOHN MULL'S MEATS
AND ROAD KILL GRILL.
YOU WANT SOME BRISKET?
YES, SIR.
THE FOOD IS FANTASTIC.
ENJOY THAT NOW.
CHUCK MAKES
THE BEST BARBECUE IN TOWN.
THAT'D BE CHUCK FROMMER,
JOHN MULL'S GRANDSON.
SO YOUR GRANDFATHER OPENS
THIS PLACE IN THE '40s.
THERE'S NO ELECTRICITY HERE
IN THE STICKS.
I MEAN, THIS HAD TO BE
STICK STICKS.
WHY OUT HERE?
IT WAS CHEAP.
THEN YOUR DAD HAD IT,
THEN YOUR UNCLE HAD IT,
AND THEN YOU GOT IT
IN '81.
IT STARTED OUT IN BUTCHERING,
AND IT TURNED INTO...
EVERYTHING.
WOULD YOU LIKE SOME RIBS?
HOW ABOUT SOME CHICKEN?
A LITTLE BRISKET?
I NEED TO GET
THE HOT LINKS.
LINKS ARE REALLY HOT.
YOU GOTTA BE CAREFUL.
A HOT LINK? NOW YOU KNOW
THESE ARE WORLD-FAMOUS.
TELL ME ABOUT
THAT HOT LINK, BROTHER.
THAT HOT LINK IS THE BEST.
NOW IN LOUISIANA
AND TEXAS AND THOSE PARTS,
PEOPLE UNDERSTAND
WHAT A HOT LINK IS.
IT'S A SPICY SAUSAGE,
BUT NOT OVERLY SPICY.
AND I THINK THAT THE REST
OF THE COUNTRY NEEDS
TO KIND OF GET IN WITH THAT,
BECAUSE IT'S A FANTASTIC
SAUSAGE, WOULD YOU AGREE?
OH, YEAH, MOST DEFINITELY.
SO YOU'RE GONNA
CUT THIS DOWN,
YOU'RE GONNA PROCESS IT,
AND CASE IT?
YES, SIR.
ALL HERE?
MM-HMM.
♪♪♪
AND WHAT ARE WE CUTTIN'?
THIS IS THE SHOULDER CLOD.
THIS IS THE INSIDE PART
OF THE...
SHOULDER.
LOOK AT HOW SHARP
THE KNIFE IS.
I LIKE YOUR HOOK, CAPTAIN.
THIS IS A "COME HERE" HOOK.
(laughs)
I'M JEALOUS. YOU GET TO
COME OUT HERE
AND JUST CUT MEAT UP
AND PLAY BUTCHER.
YEAH, THAT'D BE
KINDA COOL, WOULDN'T IT?
(chuckles)
(chuckling) IF IT WASN'T
YOUR JOB.
HAVE ONE--
(both laugh)
THERE YOU GO.
WE'RE GONNA GRIND THE MEAT
FOR THE HOT LINKS.
NO NECKTIES ALLOWED.
AND YOU WONDER WHERE
PLAY-DOH GOT THEIR IDEA.
RED SPAGHETTI.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE EMULSION.
THE EMULSION WILL GIVE US
A BETTER PENETRATION
TO THE MEAT.
(clicks)
(whirring)
WHAT, ARE WE MAKING SNOW CONES?
EXACTLY.
THIS SHOULD BE COOL.
GONNA ADD MEAT TO IT.
WHY ARE WE ADDING
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF MEAT
IN THERE, JUST AS A--
JUST SOMETHING FOR IT
TO BIND TO...
EXACTLY.
TILL IT BECOMES A MEDIUM?
LIKE A MEAT SLUSHIE.
EXACTLY.
HMM. LET ME GET MY STRAW OUT.
OKAY.
(laughs)
THIS IS MILK POWDER.
ANY TIME YOU BREAK DOWN
THE MEAT,
YOU ACTUALLY TAKE AWAY
PROTEIN,
SO YOU ADD MORE PROTEIN
BACK TO IT.
SALT.
WE GOT BLACK PEPPER.
SODIUM NITRITE.
YEP, YOU GOTTA HAVE
THE PINK IN THERE.
IT'S A PRESERVATIVE
AND IT KEEPS THE COLOR.
CORIANDER. GARLIC.
CARAWAY.
HICKORY.
SMOKE POWDER.
SHOULD BUY THAT COMPANY.
NUTMEG, PAPRIKA,
AND CAYENNE PEPPER.
(whistles) IT DOES HAVE
A HOT CHARACTERISTIC TO IT,
BUT IT'S NOT HOT LIKE YOU'RE
BURNING YOUR MOUTH OFF.
EXACTLY. NOW WE'RE
GONNA ADD SOME WATER.
EVERYBODY IN THE POOL.
IT'S A MEAT SLURPEE SNOW CONE.
(whirring)
LOOKS TASTY, DON'T IT?
YOU WANT ME TO GO GET
THE CONES?
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA MIX
THE HOT LINKS NOW.
NOW THE SLUSHIE GOES IN.
(whirring)
(Guy) OKAY. SO NOW
WE'VE GOT OUR MIX.
EVERYTHING'S COMBINED.
LOOK AT THAT SAUSAGE-MAKING
MONSTER.
NO, I WAS TALKING ABOUT YOU.
(laughs)
LET'S ROLL.
THIS IS A HYDRAULIC STUFFER.
PISTON'S GONNA COME UP
FROM THE BOTTOM?
EXACTLY.
THIS IS THE CASING.
WE'RE GONNA ACTUALLY PUT THAT
ON THE STUFFING HORN RIGHT HERE.
TIE THE END OFF.
(whirring)
HERE WE GO. AND YOU GONNA
RUN IT WITH A THUMB GAUGE?
YES, SIR.
WOW!
THAT IS JUST YAHTZEE!
(button clicks, whirring stops)
AND NOW WILL YOU TIE THEM OFF
OR TWIST 'EM OFF?
WE'RE GONNA TWIST 'EM OFF.
GRAB IT,
MOVE IT DOWN SO?
MM-HMM.
GIVE THIS ONE
A LITTLE TWIST?
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD AT THAT.
I MADE A FEW SAUSAGES
IN MY DAY, SON.
YOU DID GOOD.
THEN WHAT HAPPENS?
HANG 'EM ON A SMOKE STICK.
WHERE THEY'LL CURE
FOR 16 HOURS.
THEN THEY'LL HIT 'EM
WITH APPLE WOOD SMOKE
FOR ANOTHER SIX.
(Chuck) AND THEN PUT 'EM
BACK ON THE GRILL
JUST TO GIVE THEM
SOME GRILL MARKS.
HOLY MOLY.
(sizzling)
ALL RIGHT, LET'S TRY
A SAUSAGE.
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL THE JUICE IN THAT.
MMM. WHEN IT SNAPS,
YOU KNOW IT'S GOOD.
THAT SNAPS.
(snaps fingers twice)
THE HOT LINK IS OUTSTANDING.
THIS AIN'T NO HOT DOG.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SPICIER THAN
I WAS GONNA EXPECT IT TO BE.
AWESOME FAT RATIO.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THAT FAT--
(mouth full)
JUST--JUST THE PERFECT GRIND.
I'M SUCH A HOT LINK FAN.
THIS HAS GOTTA BE
ONE OF THE BEST.
NOT JUST ON TRIPLE "D."
I'M TALKING IN GENERAL.
OUTSTANDING.
YOU'RE SAVING YOURSELF
FOR THAT HOT LINK.
(laughter)
HE JUST DOES IT RIGHT.
THAT'S ALL I CAN SAY.
IT HAS A SPARK ON IT,
BUT IT DOESN'T HURT YOU.
(mouth full)
DUDE, GET YOURSELF READY.
YOU BUILD IT...
(whispers) THEY WILL COME.
♪♪♪
WHEN WE COME BACK...
THE RIBS ARE PERFECTLY COOKED.
JUST DELICIOUS.
WE'RE ON TO THE RACK...
IT'S ALL IN THE KNIFE.
AND I'M TRYIN'
TO KEEP AN OPEN MIND.
YOU'RE GONNA BOIL
THE RIBS?
I'M CONFUSED.
YOU'RE GONNA SOON FIND OUT.
♪♪♪
WHEN EVERYBODY TALKS
ABOUT LAS VEGAS,
IT'S THE SHOWS, THE STRIP,
AND CASINOS.
BUT AFTER THEY VISIT
JOHN MULL'S ROAD KILL GRILL...
(laughing)
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY'RE
GONNA BE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU GOT IT--BARBECUE.
THE BEST BARBECUE YOU CAN FIND.
DUDE'S CRANKIN' OUT REAL-DEAL
BARBECUE IN THE BACKYARD?
LET'S JUST KEEP THIS
BETWEEN US, RIGHT?
EXACTLY.
ARE YOU ENJOYING THAT, J.D.?
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
YOU'RE AT CHUCK'S HOUSE.
HE'S NOT JUST THE BUTCHER.
I MEAN, HE'S AN ARTIST.
WOULD YOU LIKE
SOME RIBS, SIR?
YES, SIR.
(man) AND THE RIBS
ARE PERFECTLY COOKED.
AHH, NOTHING BETTER.
THIS IS GONNA BE THE MARINADE
WE DO FOR THE RIBS?
CORRECT.
YOU MIGHT WANNA STEP BACK
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA ADD
SALT, SOME SUGAR,
TOMATO POWDER, GARLIC.
YOU JUST MAD-SCIENTIST CREATED
THIS STUFF ON YOUR OWN?
YOU BETCHA. ONION.
AND I DOWNWIND
FROM THIS RIGHT NOW,
OR ARE YOU GETTING
AS MUCH OF IT AS I AM?
(laughing)
OH, I'M GETTING IT AS MUCH.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE
SOLIDS.
(coughing)
GOT A BIG HIT OF THAT.
(laughing) RED PEPPER.
(tearing)
HICKORY SMOKE POWDER.
I GOT SOMETHING RIGHT HERE
ON THE SIDE OF MY MOUTH?
(laughs)
VINEGAR POWDER.
THIS ONE WILL TIGHTEN YOU
RIGHT UP.
(coughing)
(laughing) BLACK PEPPER.
IT'S NEVER COMING OUT OF
THE OUTFIT, THAT'S FOR SURE.
(both laughing)
(clicks)
LOT OF SPICES ARE
GETTING TO KNOW EACH OTHER
IN A VERY INTIMATE WAY.
(laughing)
BRING IT!
ALL RIGHT!
(whistles and inhales)
I FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE WILLY WONKA,
AND I JUST ATE, LIKE,
THAT 9-COURSE MEAL.
(laughs)
(whistles)
THIS MIXTURE THAT WE JUST MADE
WILL BE THE MARINADE
FOR THE RIBS PRIOR TO...
BOILING THEM IN IT.
WHOA, HO, WHOA, WHOA,
WAIT, TIME... (whistles)
THIS--OKAY.
TO WHAT-ING THEM?
BOILING THEM.
THE WHAT?
THE RIBS.
TURN ON THE BAND SAW.
(laughs)
I HAVE ONLY BEEN TAUGHT
AND TOLD FOREVER
THAT YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BOIL THE MEAT
BECAUSE IT JUST
BRINGS OUT THE FLAVOR--
SUCKS ALL THAT FLAVOR
OUT OF THE BONES.
THAT'S WHY WE BOIL IT
IN THIS MARINADE,
IS WE'RE ACTUALLY BRINGING
THAT FLAVOR BACK TO IT.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
I'M--LISTEN.
YOUR HOUSE.
I'M JUST A...
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I AM.
(chuckles)
I'M CONFUSED.
YOU'RE GONNA SOON FIND OUT.
RIB-BOILIN'
CRAZY SON OF A GUN.
ANYTHING ELSE
I NEED TO KNOW ABOUT
HERE IN THE GYPSY MEAT MARKET?
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA TUMBLE 'EM
WITH THIS.
ARE THEY EVER GONNA
GET SMOKE? THAT'S IT?
JUST FROM THE CHARCOAL,
THAT'S IT.
WHAT KIND OF RIBS
ARE WE USING, BY THE WAY?
BABY BACK, ST. LOUIS?
ST. LOUIS STYLE.
OKAY.
IT'S MEATIER.
IT'S GOT BETTER FLAVOR.
BETTER FLAVOR. OKAY.
EXACTLY.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA LIFT
THE SKIRT,
SQUARE IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
WATCHING YOU WORK THAT KNIFE
IS LIKE WATCHING A SURGEON.
IT'S ALL IN THE KNIFE.
THESE ARE RIB TIPS RIGHT HERE.
AND THEN THIS
WE'LL USE FOR SAUSAGE.
YOU'RE STILL KEEPING
THE BUTCHER MIND
ABOUT EVERYTHING
THAT YOU DO HERE.
IT'S "WASTE NOT, WANT NOT."
EXACTLY.
HOW LONG'S THIS GONNA
TUMBLE FOR?
FOR ABOUT 16 HOURS.
WHAT?!
SERIOUSLY, HOW LONG
WILL YOU TUMBLE THIS?
16--16 HOURS.
DIG IT. OKAY, LET'S GO.
IF THIS GOES MISSING,
DON'T LOOK IN MY CAR.
(laughs)
OKAY?
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT SOME VACUUM ON IT.
WHAT KINDA PUMP IS THAT?
(whirring)
A SELF PUMP.
WE'RE NOT FILLING AN INNER TUBE
UP AT THE RIVER.
(hisses)
THESE WILL SAVE YOU
A LOT OF TIME.
IT'S NOT ONLY TO GET
THE MARINADE IN IT,
BUT IT'S ALSO A TENDERIZING
PROCESS,
LIKE A MASSAGING PROCESS
THAT GOES ON IT...
CORRECT.
WITHOUT BREAKING
THE MEAT DOWN.
DID I PAY ATTENTION
IN MEAT CLASS?
YOU DID GOOD, MAN.
YOU DID REAL GOOD.
THANK YOU MUCH.
(hisses)
AFTER A 16-HOUR TUMBLE,
THEY'RE BOILED IN THE MARINADE
AND HIT THE GRILL.
A LITTLE NINJA DUST.
I LIKE A THIN RACK.
THAT'S MY RACK RIGHT BACK
IN THERE. THERE YOU GO.
SO THAT'S OUR RIB,
BOILED 45 MINUTES.
AND THIS IS DRY SEASONING
WITH NO SAUCE ON IT.
NO SAUCE.
(mouth full) BY NO MEANS
DOES THIS LACK IN FLAVOR.
IT'S NOT PULLING OFF.
IT'S GOT--
IT'S GOT NICE TEXTURE,
NICE CHEW TO IT.
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
I LIKE TO SEE.
DIFFERENT TEXTURE
THAN WHEN IT'S SMOKED.
JUICY, TENDER, GREAT FLAVOR.
AND THERE'S NO SAUCE.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU THIS,
DUDE.
IT'S A REAL-DEAL RIB.
YOU'RE REAL-DEAL, MAN.
HEY, I APPRECIATE IT, MAN.
I AIN'T JOKING AROUND.
RIBS ARE PERFECTLY COOKED.
IT'S JUICY.
JUST DELICIOUS.
THE WAY HE PREPARES THEM,
THEY COME OUT GREAT.
YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO BITE IT.
YOU CAN JUST PULL IT
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
SO HE MAKES ONE OF THE BEST
BARBECUE IN TOWN.
WHEN I DROVE UP,
I REALLY LOOKED AND I SAID,
"OH, MY GOSH," I MEAN,
"I GOT A GUY HERE
WITH A COUPLE SMOKERS
MAKING SOME BEEF JERKY."
AND IT'S--DUDE, YOU ARE DOING
COMPETITION-LEVEL MEAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE LIKE TO HEAR.
REALLY GOOD.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(spraying)
(Diane laughing)
WAIT--
AAH!
(laughter)