I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
THREE, TWO, ONE, GO.
WE GOT THE PEDAL
TO THE MEDAL...
OH, MY... GAH!
AND TAKING THE TURN
FOR UNEXPECTED EATS.
I'M SCARED.
IN STILLWATER, MINNESOTA...
ARE YOU SURE YOU DON'T
WANNA TRY ONE MORE THING?
THE BARBECUE PIRATE JOINT...
ARR!
STORMIN'
THE FLAVOR TOWN SHIP...
NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
NO ONE SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT GHOST PEPPERS.
WITH A JAMAICAN TAKE
ON TACOS AND WINGS.
THIS IS NOTHING.
CHILDREN EAT THIS.
(baby voice) MAMA.
(laughs)
IN SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA...
THE DAY HAS FINALLY COME.
THE SPOT THAT KICKED IT
ALL OFF FOR ME
WITH A MASH-UP OF FLAVORS
I TOTALLY DIG.
AND IN PORTSMOUTH, VIRGINIA...
AND I THOUGHT YOU WERE
JUST A HOT DOG GUY.
(laughs)
THE HOT DOG STAND
WITH A HEART THAT'S PUMPIN'
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
IF YOU THINK YOUR MOM MADE
GOOD CHICKEN AND DUMPLING,
WAIT TILL YOU TRY THIS.
THAT'S A CALL-OUT TO MOMS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
(man) WOW.
THIS IS GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
(door closes)
I'M HERE IN BEAUTIFUL
BUT A LITTLE BIT CHILLY
STILLWATER, MINNESOTA,
RIGHT ON THE ST. CROIX RIVER--
THAT'S WHAT DIVIDES WISCONSIN
AND MINNESOTA--
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT'S DOING--
GET THIS--
CARIBBEAN BARBECUE.
NOT SOMETHING YOU HEAR
EVERY DAY--CARIBBEAN BARBECUE.
I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS SMALLEY'S.
THIS AIN'T YOUR TRADITIONAL
BARBECUE JOINT.
JERK CHICKEN SANDWICH.
IT'S TRADITIONAL
JAMAICAN BARBECUE.
SPICES THAT THEY USE IN THIS,
YOU CAN'T GET ANYWHERE ELSE.
TRIPLE SIX WINGS
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S JUST KIND OF AN EXPLOSION
OF DIFFERENT KINDS OF FLAVORS.
THERE'S NOT ANYTHING ELSE
LIKE IT IN TOWN.
'CAUSE THERE'S NOBODY ELSE
QUITE LIKE OWNER
SHAWN SMALLEY.
(laughs)
HE CAME UP COOKING AT ONE OF
MINNEAPOLIS' BEST RESTAURANTS,
BUT LOVED DOING JERK BARBECUE
ON THE SIDE.
WE'D HAVE BIG BARBECUES
ON SUNDAYS.
AND THIS IS WHAT WE'D DO
JUST FOR FUN.
THEN HE WENT TO JAMAICA,
HONED HIS SKILLS,
AND OPENED THIS JOINT,
ARMED WITH SOME ISLAND SECRETS.
SMOKED WITH PIMENTO WOOD.
WITH PIMENTO WOOD?
PIMENTO WOOD.
REALLY?
GET IT IMPORTED FROM JAMAICA.
DUDE! THAT IS AWESOME!
AND THEN YOU GRIND IT UP
FOR THE SMOKER?
YEP.
GIVING THIS FAN FAVORITE
SOME UNMISTAKABLE FLAVOR.
JERK PORK TACOS.
YOU GO TO ALL THAT EFFORT
JUST TO MAKE THIS PORK TACO?
EXACTLY.
OKAY. LET'S SEE IT.
GONNA MAKE SOME SMOKED PORK
FOR OUR JERK PORK TACOS.
BOSTON BUTT.
SEASON IT WITH
A FAIR AMOUNT OF SALT.
OOH, REALLY?
SECRET FAMILY RECIPE?
(laughs)
HOW LONG YOU GONNA LEAVE
THE SALT CRUST ON IT?
GO RIGHT TO THE SMOKER
WITH IT.
AND HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA GO DOWN?
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN
FIVE AND SEVEN HOURS.
225?
YEP.
CUT SOME OF THAT OFF.
MMM! YOU SERIOUS?
JUST SALT CRUST?
THAT'S ALL WE DO.
PIMENTO WOOD,
IT'S A REALLY UNIQUE FLAVOR.
WE DON'T LIKE TO COVER IT UP
WITH A BUNCH OF STUFF.
JUST LET IT SHINE.
HAD WE NOT GONE
THROUGH THIS TOGETHER,
YOU WOULD BE HARD-PRESSED
TO TELL ME
THAT THAT WAS NOT DRY-RUBBED
WITH A VARIETY OF SPICES.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THIS IS OUR BASE MARINADE.
WE'LL TURN THAT
INTO OUR JERK SAUCE.
FIRE IT UP.
JAMAICAN ALLSPICE,
WHOLE WHITE PEPPER,
FRESH GARLIC,
FRESH SHALLOTS,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
FRESH THYME.
LOOK AT ALL THAT THYME.
GREEN ONIONS DEFINITELY.
GREEN ONIONS.
THEN HERE'S OUR JAMAICAN SOY.
JAMAICAN SOY?
SO IS THAT KIND OF LIKE
A SWEET SOY?
YEAH, IT'S A LITTLE BIT
MORE RICH.
OKAY.
LET ME TURN THIS BAD BOY ON.
(whirs)
WHAT ARE YOU
THINKING ABOUT?
(whirring stops)
PUPPIES.
(laughter)
YOU DON'T THINK YOU CAN MAKE
FOOD THIS CREATIVE
AND THIS WEIRD IF YOU'RE
NOT THINKING ABOUT PUPPIES.
(laughing)
ALL RIGHT, NEXT UP?
IT'S OUR BOURBON BEACH SAUCE.
KIND OF A HOMAGE TO THE GUYS
ON BOURBON BEACH.
OKAY.
IT'S OUR JERK MARINADE.
(tapping)
RIDICULOUS.
SCOTCH BONNET PEPPERS.
THE ONLY PAST THAT
IS THE GHOST.
LITTLE VINEGAR.
AND NOW WE BLEND.
(whirring)
(whirring stops)
OH, MY GOSH, DUDE!
(laughs)
WHOO! THAT'LL EAT
A TATTOO OFF, MAN.
YOU MAKE SAUCE
HOTTER THAN THAT?
THIS IS NOTHING.
CHILDREN EAT THIS.
(baby voice) MAMA.
(laughs)
PUT A TORTILLA
ON THE FLATTOP,
THROW SOME PORK ON THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR, UH,
JERK SAUCE THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
(sizzling)
OUR TORTILLA. THAT PORK THAT'S
BEEN COOKING IN THE JERK SAUCE.
GRILLED SCALLION AIOLI.
I CAN SMELL THE HEAT
FROM HERE.
(laughs) SHREDDED CABBAGE.
PICO.
QUESO FRESCO.
A LITTLE EXTRA
CILANTRO FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
(mouth full) FORTUNATELY
YOU COOKED THAT SAUCE DOWN
A LITTLE BIT,
'CAUSE IT'S NOT
AS THERMONUCLEAR
AS I HAD ANTICIPATED.
THAT PORK IS SUPER TENDER,
HAS FANTASTIC FLAVOR.
I LOVE HOW YOU MARRIED
EVERYTHING ELSE TOGETHER.
BETWEEN THE PORK,
THE JERK SAUCE,
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
HABAÑEROS COMING THROUGH.
MM.
NOW THEY'RE STARTING
TO COME THROUGH MORE.
THEY'RE SHOWING UP.
(laughs)
(mouth full)
I GOTTA TELL YOU,
YOU COULD BE IN A TACO TRUCK
COMPETITION WITH THAT.
AWESOME.
JERK PORK TACOS.
I AM ADDICTED TO THE TACOS.
THEY DON'T EVEN NEED
TO ASK ME ANYMORE.
THEY KNOW I WANT
JERK PORK TACOS.
(man) SHAWN IS THE BEST OWNER.
HE IS AN INCREDIBLE CHEF,
AND HE'S A PIRATE.
ARR! DID HE SAY "PIRATE"?
HE'S GOT THE FULL-ON BEARD,
THE LONG HAIR,
TATTOOS EVERYWHERE.
AND THE JOINT'S FULL OF BOOTY,
LIKE FULL-SIZE PIRATES,
CANNONS,
AND EVEN HOUSE-MADE RUM.
TELL ME ABOUT
THE PIRATE THING.
IT'S SOMETHING I'VE ALWAYS
BEEN INFATUATED WITH.
THEY HAD A PIRATE WEDDING.
YOU HAD A PIRATE WEDDING?
YOU KNOW IT.
GUYS WANNA SEE THE PIRATE
WEDDING? ARR, YOU DO!
(cheering)
YOU'RE SLIGHTLY SCARED OF HIM,
BUT I KNOW HE'S AWESOME.
AND SINCE PIRATES STOPPED
TROLLING
AMERICAN RIVERS IN THE 1800s,
SMALLEY HAS FOUND A NEW WAY
TO WREAK SOME HAVOC...
THINGS ARE SPICY HERE?
OH, YEAH.
BRINGING PAIN TO THE PEOPLE
WITH THE SAUCE FOR HIS WINGS.
WE'VE GOT MILD, MEDIUM, HOT,
THEN WE'VE GOT
OUR OTHER OPTIONS.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
YOU SHOULD TRY
THE TRIPLE SIX WINGS.
THEY'RE NOT MINNESOTA HOT.
THEY'RE HOT HOT.
AHH!
♪♪
AT SMALLEY'S
CARIBBEAN BARBECUE
IN STILLWATER, MINNESOTA,
THE JERK PORK TACOS
HAVE SOME ZIP.
AND THE CHICKEN WINGS
HAVE SOME ZING.
WHOO!
SUPER HOT WINGS.
BUT OWNER SHAWN SMALLEY CLAIMS
I HAVEN'T KNOWN REAL HEAT
TILL I'VE TRIED
HIS TRIPLE SIX WINGS.
TRIPLE SIX WINGS?
YOU KNOW IT.
HUH. YOU GUYS THINK
I SHOULD DO THIS?
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
I'M DOWN FOR THE CHALLENGE.
I'M NOT GONNA LIE.
IT'S GONNA HURT.
SERIOUSLY?
I PROMISE.
WHY DO YOU HAVE THIS
ON THE MENU?
PEOPLE FOR SOME REASON
WANT IT.
ARR!
PUT IT ON THE TABLE.
AND I'M SCARED.
ALL RIGHT. THIS IS THE ESSENCE
OF ALL OUR PEPPERS.
GHOST PEPPERS, HABAÑEROS,
SCOTCH BONNETS.
YOU TAKE ALL OF THOSE
AND PUREE THEM INTO THAT?
YEAH. PUREE 'EM, STRAIN 'EM.
BASICALLY ALL THE HOT
GOES INTO HERE.
WE CALL THIS OUR DEATH JUICE.
SO LET ME ASK YOU THIS.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD THIS?
I TASTE EVERY BATCH,
AND THEN RUN AROUND
SCREAMING LIKE A LITTLE GIRL.
IT'S THAT HOT?
(sighs) LET'S DO IT.
START WITH OUR DEATH JUICE.
OH, WE'RE GONNA
CONCENTRATE IT?
OH, YEAH.
NEXT WE HAVE SOME
FRANK'S RED HOT.
FOR COLOR?
COLOR, AND I JUST KINDA LIKE
THE FLAVOR IT BRINGS OUT.
VINEGAR. HOMEMADE CURRY.
SMELLS DELICIOUS.
THAT WAY IT'S NOT JUST HOT.
GIVES IT A LITTLE JAZZ
TO IT, YOU KNOW?
SOME SALT, SOME MORE PEPPER.
AND NOW GASOLINE
AND TWO PARTS ETHER.
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
ALL YOU CAN.
ALL YOU CAN. GO FOR IT.
AND THEN... GHOST PEPPERS.
NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
IN YOU GO.
NO. NO ONE SAID ANYTHING
ABOUT GHOST PEPPERS.
WHAT'S THE SCOVILLE RATING
ON GHOST PEPPERS?
SCOVILLE UNITS MEASURE
HOW A PEPPER'S HOT.
JALAPEÑO OVER HERE.
SCOTCH BONNET HERE.
GHOST PEPPER...
(taps)
UP THERE.
THIS IS NOT GONNA BE GOOD.
HERE WE ARE. THE SERRANO
PEPPER IS 23,000.
TABASCO SAUCE
IS 3,500.
BHUT JOLOKIA CHILI--
THAT'S THE ONE?
YEP.
OH, THAT'S AWESOME.
'CAUSE THAT'S A RATING
OF A 855,000
TO 1.4 MILLION.
I THINK WE NEED ONE MORE.
NOW WHAT ARE GONNA DO
WITH THIS?
WE JUST GIVE IT A STIR,
CRANK ON THE HEAT ABOUT AN HOUR,
REDUCE IT DOWN, AND PUREE IT.
(whirs)
AND IT'S READY
FOR SOME WINGS.
(sizzling)
OH-OH-OH-OH-OH!
LET'S DO SOME WINGS.
ALL RIGHT. THIS IS IT.
YES.
THE DEATH JUICE.
EXACTLY.
THE GHOST PEPPERS.
MM-HMM.
OH. THIS IS GONNA BE
TERRIBLE.
ALL RIGHT.
DUMP THAT ON THERE.
A LITTLE TOSS.
THERE THEY ARE!
ALL RIGHT.
OH, MY... GAH!
I CAN'T EVEN--
AHH, THE VAPORS!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
I'VE BROUGHT IN
MY BUDDIES, MY CREW,
THE CULINARY GANGSTERS.
SO FIRST LET ME INTRODUCE
DUSTIN ROTA,
MESSERSCHMITT,
AND REID.
(laughter)
OKAY. EVERYBODY
GRAB A WINGY.
READY?
(laughter and murmuring)
FIVE, FOUR, THREE,
TWO, ONE, GO.
GOTTA EAT THE WHOLE WING?
OH, GOD.
(coughing)
I'M LEAVIN'.
(gasping)
OH, MY GOD!
(laughter)
HOW'S THIS LOOK?
YOU DIDN'T TELL US
ABOUT THIS.
(groans)
HEY, YOU WANT ME
TO BLOWTORCH YOUR FACE OFF?
(laughter)
(indistinct conversations)
BLOWTORCH YOUR FACE OFF
REAL QUICK.
OH, MY GOD.
(laughter)
I'LL DROP IN THE MOST
MISERABLE--
HEY, MILK FOR SALE!
(laughter)
HE'S LACTOSE INTOLERANT.
(laughter continues)
OHH!
DID EVERYBODY EAT THE WHOLE
WING? I ATE THE WHOLE WING.
AHH!
I KNEW WHAT I WAS GETTING
MYSELF INTO!
(laughter)
OH, GOD, IT HURTS
ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
(laughter continues)
TRIPLE SIX WINGS
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S PROBABLY THE HOTTEST
THING I'VE EVER HAD.
YOUR EYES START WATERING,
YOUR MOUTH FEELS ON FIRE.
AND THE NOSE RUNS, TOO,
A LITTLE BIT.
NEVER, EVER ORDER
THE 666 WING HERE
AT SMALLEY'S PIRATE BAR.
I'M LOSING FEELING
IN MY TONGUE.
(slurring) I'M GONNA
SIGN OFF RIGHT NOW.
(laughter)
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
UP NEXT...
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS.
I'M HEADED HOME
TO SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA...
THIS IS MY MOM PENNY
AND MY DAD JIM.
WHERE MY FIRST LOVE...
DOUBLE GOLD MEDAL WINNER,
SONOMA COUNTY HARVEST FAIR.
IS STILL KEEPING ME
ON MY TOES.
IT'S THE BEST EVER.
I MEAN, YOU SURPASSED ME
ONCE AGAIN.
I THOUGHT I TAUGHT YOU
EVERYTHING, BUT...
♪♪
HERE WE ARE, MY HOMETOWN,
SANTA ROSA, CALIFORNIA.
NOW TRIPLE "D" HAS BEEN HERE
A BUNCH OF TIMES--
I MEAN, HANK'S CREEKSIDE,
WILLIE BIRD'S,
CAFE CITTI, SCHELLVILLE GRILL,
JUST TO NAME A FEW.
BUT ONE OF THE QUESTIONS
YOU KEEP ASKING ME IS,
"GUY, WHEN ARE WE GONNA SEE
ONE OF YOUR RESTAURANTS
ON TRIPLE 'D'?"
WELL, GUESS WHAT.
THE DAY HAS FINALLY COME.
HERE WE ARE,
MY FIRST RESTAURANT--
JOHNNY GARLIC'S
CALIFORNIA PASTA GRILL.
BUFFALO MEAT LOAF.
THIS IS A VERY UNIQUE MENU.
CAJUN CHICKEN FETTUCCINE.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF SO MANY
DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
ASIAN BLENDED WITH MEXICAN
BLENDED WITH ITALIAN
BLENDED WITH THE CAJUN.
CAJUN CHICKEN ALFREDO.
IT'S A DIVERSE APPROACH
THAT I CAN SAY
I DEFINITELY INHERITED.
THIS IS MY MOM PENNY
AND MY DAD JIM.
BOTH OF THEM WERE
VERY INSTRUMENTAL IN SEEING...
(chuckles) THAT JOHNNY GARLIC'S
GOT OFF THE GROUND.
MATTER OF FACT,
THEY MORTGAGED THEIR HOUSE
RIGHT BEFORE THEY WERE
READY TO RETIRE
TO OPEN THE RESTAURANT.
SO WAS IT WORTH IT?
(laughs)
(laughs) ABSOLUTELY, GUY.
AND YOU CAN FIND
MY MOM AND DAD'S INFLUENCE
ALL OVER THE JOINT.
THIS DISH RIGHT HERE IS
A JOHNNY GARLIC'S FAVORITE.
AND IT WAS ACTUALLY
INTRODUCED TO ME
BY MY MOM PENNY,
AND SHE SAID,
"YOU ARE GONNA LOVE THIS.
I'VE GOT THIS THING,
IT'S CALLED
AN ONION TORTILLA CAKE."
ONION, TORTILLA, AND CAKE.
THERE'S NO WAY
IT WAS GONNA TASTE GOOD.
WELL, I TRIED IT.
IT WAS DYNAMITE.
AND THIS IS MY SPIN ON IT.
PRESENTING THE GRILLED ONION
AND GARLIC TORTILLA STACK.
WE'RE GONNA CARAMELIZE
SOME ONIONS FIRST.
AND THE KEY ON THIS ONE
IS GOING LOW AND SLOW
AND REALLY LETTING THOSE
SUGARS DEVELOP
AND REALLY BRINGING OUT THAT
DEEP, RICH COLOR
THAT YOU GET WHEN YOU
CARAMELIZE THE ONIONS.
SWEAT A LITTLE,
WE GET THE BUTTER COATING IT,
AND NOW WE'RE GOING TO
ADD SOME SUGAR TO IT.
REALLY EXPEDITE
THE CARAMELIZATION PROCESS.
KEEP ON REDUCING.
WE DRAW THAT RESIDUAL SUGAR OUT
OF THE ONION THAT'S IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA GET 'EM
TO A NICE GOLDEN BROWN.
NEXT?
START WITH SOME MAYONNAISE.
A LITTLE FOOD LUBE.
BALSAMIC VINEGAR,
CILANTRO,
ROASTED GARLIC,
PARMESAN CHEESE.
I KNOW IT'S AN ODD
COMBINATION OF INGREDIENTS,
BUT TRUST ME, IT WORKS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR ONIONS.
NOW COMES THE POWER TOOL.
(whirring)
(whirring stops)
OKAY, THIS GREAT MIXTURE--
GUESS WHERE IT GOES NEXT.
BETWEEN FANTASTIC
LOCALLY MADE FLOUR TORTILLAS.
A HEALTHY PORTION HERE.
SPREAD IT EVENLY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE 12 LAYERS
OF THIS.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK
TO MAKE JUST AN APPETIZER...
BUT I WILL TELL YOU WHAT--
YOU'LL NEVER FIND IT
ANYWHERE ELSE LIKE THIS.
ARE YOU DONE WITH THIS
ALREADY, BETTY CROCKER?
DONE--YOU KNOW WHAT?
IF IT'S NOT PERFECT,
I DON'T WANT IT
OUT OF MY KITCHEN.
(laughing)
WE CAN'T JUST MAKE IT,
CUT IT, AND GO TO THE GRILL.
IT TAKES SOME TIME
TO ACTUALLY SET UP.
LET 'EM SET UP OVERNIGHT.
LET IT KIND OF CONGEAL
TOGETHER,
TAKE IT OUT, SLICE IT,
GRILL IT BOTH SIDES,
A LITTLE CROSSHATCH,
THEN FINISH IT IN THE OVEN.
TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
NOW THE DIPPING SAUCE
IS THE SAME MIXTURE THAT
WE PUT INSIDE WHEN IT'S COOL.
GIVE IT A LITTLE DUNK.
(mouth full) THE TEXTURE'S
DYNAMITE.
THE FLAVOR IS HUGE.
GREAT HANDMADE TORTILLAS.
SMOKINESS, CRISPY.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
IT'S JUST AN EXPLOSION
OF FLAVOR.
THEY ALWAYS HAVE SOMETHING
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT
FROM THE NORM.
I MEAN, COME ON.
WHEN IT COMES
TO ONE OF MY PLACES,
WOULD YOU EXPECT
ANYTHING ELSE?
FOODS RUN INTO EACH OTHER HERE
IN A GREAT WAY.
IT'S DEFINITELY FULL OF FLAVOR.
JUST LIKE IT'S BEEN
SINCE I OPENED THE JOINT
WITH MY BUSINESS PARTNER
STEVE GRUBER
IN 1996.
WE WOULD TRAIN THE STAFF
ON HOW TO COOK
AND HOW TO SERVE TABLES,
AND THEN AT NIGHT--
'CAUSE WE SLEPT HERE--
WE WOULD...
WE'D DO CONSTRUCTION
ALL NIGHT LONG,
GET UP IN THE MORNING,
AND BACK ON FOOD DEVELOPMENT.
THE IDEA WAS ALWAYS
REALLY FRESH FOOD,
CONTEMPORARY FOOD.
AND THAT NO-HOLDS-BARRED
ATTITUDE
HAS LED TO DISHES LIKE
SALMON COOKED ON A CEDAR PLANK
WITH JALAPEÑOS
AND APRICOT PRESERVES,
BABY-BACK RIBS
WITH A CHERRY BARBECUE SAUCE,
AND THIS RIGHTEOUS MIXTURE
OF ASIAN AND MEXICAN FUSION.
ORDER IN--
SASHIMI WON TACOS.
IT'S A CROSS BETWEEN, UH,
SUSHI AND MEXICAN.
I KIND OF BEGAN
THE INVENTION
OF THIS RECIPE WITH MY BUDDY
SAMMY HAGAR IN THIS KITCHEN,
BUT MICHAEL IS GONNA
WALK US THROUGH IT.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH AHI TUNA.
THIS IS SUSHI-GRADE AHI?
YES, IT IS.
THE KEY IS TO SLICE IT THIN,
AND NOT TOO THIN,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANNA
BRUISE IT,
WE DON'T WANNA BEAT IT UP.
NOW WE'RE READY
FOR OUR SALSA.
START OUT WITH JICAMA.
SO JICAMA'S GOT THAT
REALLY NICE CRUNCH TO IT.
I DON'T THINK IT GETS
UTILIZED ENOUGH.
PEOPLE ARE KINDA SCARED
OF WHAT THIS--
THIS CRAZY RADISH IS.
BEAUTIFUL, FRESH MANGO.
FIRM FLESH. IT'S GONNA
BURST WITH FLAVOR.
RED ONION. CILANTRO.
ASIAN SWEET CHILI SAUCE.
SWEET SOY SAUCE.
JALAPEÑO.
WE WANNA GIVE IT A LITTLE
BITE, A LITTLE PEPPER.
AND A TOUCH OF SALT.
SALT PULLS OUT
A LITTLE BIT OF THE MOISTURE,
PULLS OUT A LITTLE BIT
OF THE FLAVOR,
AND YOU'LL MIX SOME OF THAT
WITH THE AHI.
SO REALLY NICE AND LIGHT.
JUST KINDA MIXING IT UP,
LETTING THE FLAVORS
MARRY A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS READY. WHAT WE'RE
GONNA DO IS LET THIS SIT.
GONNA LET IT GATHER
THE FLAVORS.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR WONTONS.
THESE ARE THIN. WE DON'T
WANNA OVERDO THEM.
ABOUT 15 SECONDS,
AND WE'LL BE READY TO GO.
AND WE'RE DONE.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
LET 'EM DRAIN OFF HERE.
WHILE THESE ARE COOLING DOWN,
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE THE WASABI
CREAM SAUCE.
HEAVY CREAM.
LOVE THIS.
SALT, SUGAR, LEMON JUICE,
RICE VINEGAR.
SO A LITTLE ACID COMPONENT,
A LITTLE SUGAR COMPONENT,
SALT COMPONENT, GETTING
ALL THE FLAVOR PROFILES,
AND NOW THIS RIGHT HERE--
THIS IS THE KICKER.
THIS IS THE HEAT COMPONENT.
WASABI POWDER.
SOUR CREAM TO TIGHTEN IT UP.
THEN THE WHISKING STARTS.
THE KEY IS TO WHISK THIS UP
AND LET THESE FLAVORS
MARRY TOGETHER.
FRESH PEA SHOOTS,
JUST LIKE YOU LOVE.
WE GET 'EM IN DAILY.
GONNA HIT THIS WITH
A LITTLE EEL SAUCE.
EEL SAUCE IS REALLY CRAZY.
YOU'RE KINDA THINKING ABOUT--
OF A THICK, STICKY SOY SAUCE.
GONNA FILL THESE TACOS UP.
THE WASABI CREAM ON THERE
THAT WE JUST MADE.
TOUCH 'EM WITH EEL SAUCE
ONE MORE TIME.
AND THE FINAL TOUCH--
WASABI MICROGREENS.
KILLER DISH.
AS YOU KNOW, GUY,
DOUBLE GOLD MEDAL WINNER,
SONOMA COUNTY HARVEST FAIR.
(crunching)
(mouth full) THE CRUNCHY SHELL,
THE FRESH AHI,
AND IT'S GOT SUCH A NICE, BIG,
BRIGHT FLAVOR WITH THE WASABI.
AND THEN THE CRUNCHY VEG--
HANDS DOWN, ONE OF MY FAVORITE
APPETIZERS HERE, MAN.
SASHIMI WON TACOS
THERE FOR YOU.
IT'S DEFINITELY UNUSUAL.
THE WASABI SAUCE
AND THE EEL SAUCE
GIVE IT A NICE LITTLE KICK.
I GET THIS ALL THE TIME.
I LOVE IT.
(Jim)
AND WE DON'T HAVE TO PAY.
IT'S EASY TO GET A NICE
COMPLIMENT ABOUT YOUR FOOD
WHEN THEY DON'T HAVE TO PAY!
YEAH!
(laughs)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO PORTSMOUTH, VIRGINIA...
HEY, BATTER, BATTER.
SWING, BATTER.
WHERE AN OLD-TIME
HOT DOG STAND...
THIS IS A TRICK
I'M GONNA USE, DUDE.
IS SERVING UP
SOME NEW STANDARDS.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THIS
PETITE DANCER'S FIGURE.
(laughs)
I CAN GO BIG WHEN IT'S
CHICKEN AND DUMPLING TIME.
♪♪
I'M ABOUT 20 MINUTES SOUTH
OF NORFOLK, VIRGINIA,
IN A TOWN CALLED
PORTSMOUTH--
OR P-TOWN,
AS THE LOCALS CALL IT--
TO CHECK OUT AN OLD-SCHOOL
HOT DOG JOINT.
NOW THIS USED TO BE THE HANGOUT
FOR THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL.
BUT THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL
CLOSED ABOUT 20 YEARS AGO.
GUESS WHAT.
IT'S STILL THE LOCAL HANGOUT.
WELCOME TO HARVEY'S HOT DOGS II.
ONE FOOT-LONG
ALL THE WAY CHEESE AND KRAUT.
THE FOOD IS SO DELICIOUS.
LARGE BARBECUE WITH SLAW.
I LIKE THE MENU HERE
'CAUSE IT'S GOT HOT DOGS,
HAMBURGERS, BARBECUE.
ONE LARGE BEAN CHILI,
PICK UP.
NOW THE ORIGINAL HARVEY'S
HAS BEEN SERVING UP
HOT DOGS SINCE 1976.
BUT WHEN RICHIE
AND MICHELLE WOOD
BOUGHT IT IN 2010,
THEY DUBBED IT "PART DEUX"
AND ADDED MORE SOUTHERN COMFORT
TO THE MENU...
YOU NEED A LARGE CHICKEN
AND DUMPLING, SHAUNA?
THAT SOUTHERN BOY
JIM PATE GREW UP ON.
(Irish accent)
WHERE YOU FROM, JIMMY?
CAROLINA, ORIGINALLY.
(normal voice)
NORTH CAROLINA?
YEAH.
I GUESS WHEN YOU'RE FROM
NORTH CAROLINA,
YOU CALL IT "CAROLINA,"
AND THEN EVERYBODY ELSE
IS SUPPOSED TO CALL THEMSELVES
"SOUTHERN CAROLINA"?
THAT'S IT.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
IF YOU THINK YOUR MOM MADE
GOOD CHICKEN AND DUMPLING,
WAIT TILL YOU TRY THIS.
THAT'S A CALL-OUT TO MOMS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
(man) WOW.
THIS IS GOOD.
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN ON
YOUR CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS.
OKAY.
START WITH, UH, FLOUR.
I'LL GO A LITTLE OREGANO.
GOTTA BE SOME THYME THERE.
A LITTLE THYME ACTION.
BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE SALT.
AND NOW WE'LL ADD
THE CHICKEN STOCK.
SO YOU'RE NOT ONLY GONNA
BE PUTTING THESE DUMPLINGS
INTO CHICKEN STOCK,
BUT YOU'RE GONNA ACTUALLY
MAKE THE DUMPLING ITSELF WITH
THAT BROTH, SO IT'S PRETTY--
YES.
IT'S CHICKEN ON CHICKEN.
THESE A BIG HIT?
YEAH. I MAKE PROBABLY
2 OR 3 GALLONS OF IT,
AND IT'S GONE THE NEXT DAY.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL CALL THIS
HARVEY'S HOUSE OF CHICKEN
AND DUMPLINGS.
(laughs)
A LITTLE BENCH FLOUR.
THERE YOU GO.
HEY, BATTER, BATTER.
SWING, BATTER.
CUTTING THESE GUYS
LIKE THIS.
YOU LINE 'EM UP LIKE THAT.
RIGHT.
POP THAT IN THE FREEZER.
UH-HUH.
AND THEN THE NEXT DAY
IT'S WAY EASIER
TO TAKE THAT FROZEN PIECE,
POP IT OFF,
AND THROW IT RIGHT IN,
INSTEAD OF ALL THIS GOO.
AND THAT'S HOW WE ROLL?
YES.
LET'S MAKE SOME STOCK.
(Guy) HIT IT.
GO IN WITH THIS.
BOIL THIS CHICKEN, LET IT COOL,
AND WE'RE GONNA SHRED IT.
OKAY.
(Guy) THE FROZEN DUMPLING
BATTER--
THIS IS A TRICK
I'M GONNA USE, DUDE.
SNAP 'EM OFF
AND THROW 'EM ON IN.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL 'EM
FOR ABOUT 30, 45 MINUTES.
SO THESE START COOKING,
YOU PUT THOSE ON THE BACK,
AND THEN START THE SOUP
ON THE FRONT?
YEAH. START WITH
A LITTLE BUTTER.
CARROTS FIRST
'CAUSE THEY TAKE LONGER.
CELERY.
YEAH.
A LITTLE ONION.
ONION!
WHAT I'LL DO NEXT IS I'LL
MAKE MY ROUX RIGHT IN THE POT.
A LITTLE ROUX ON IT. OKAY.
AND I THOUGHT YOU WERE
JUST A HOT DOG GUY.
(laughs)
STOCK.
TEAMWORK.
A LITTLE HEAVY WHIP.
SLOW SIMMER MAYBE
20, 30 MINUTES,
GET IT NICE AND HOT
AND THICK--FINISHED.
THE CHICKEN SOUP IS DONE.
YEAH.
NOW WE PULL THE DUMPLINGS.
YES.
STRAIN THESE BAD BOYS OUT.
THAT'S WHAT THEY
TURNED OUT LIKE.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
NOW YOU GO WITH THE CHICKEN.
WHITE AND DARK.
YES.
AH, IT'S NICE AND HEARTY.
NOW WE SERVE IT UP.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THIS
PETITE DANCER'S FIGURE.
(laughs)
I CAN GO BIG WHEN IT'S
CHICKEN AND DUMPLING TIME.
GO RIGHT HERE.
MMM.
NICE BIG CHUNKS OF CHICKEN.
IT'S NOT ALL SHREDDED.
VEGGIES COOKED DOWN
RIGHT INTO THE SAUCE.
IT'S A CREAMY DUMPLING.
GOT A LITTLE TENDERNESS TO IT.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE THYME
COMING THROUGH THAT DUMPLING.
AWESOME JOB.
CHICKEN AND DUMPLINGS,
PICK UP.
THEY'RE HOMEMADE.
THE BROTH IS RICH, FLAVORFUL.
DAWN, I GOT A PICK-UP!
MY HUSBAND AND I COME HERE
SIX DAYS A WEEK,
AND WE WOULD COME SEVEN
IF THEY WERE OPEN. (laughs)
HAVE A PLACE LIKE THIS,
DUDE--
AN OLD-SCHOOL PLACE
WHERE YOU JUST SHOW UP--
IT'S BEEN HERE
35 YEARS-PLUS.
GOOD STUFF, MAN.
THANKS. THANKS, GUY.
APPRECIATE IT.
GOOD JOB.
MMM!
WHEN IT SNAPS, YOU KNOW
IT'S GOOD. EAT UP.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FROM THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(inhales)
I ATE THE WHOLE WING.
IT WENT ALL THE WAY INSIDE,
ALL THE WAY DOWN TO MY STOMACH.
IT'S HERE RIGHT NOW.
(inhales)
IT'S DOING...
IT'S LIKE A--
OH, GOD, IT'S HOT.
(laughter)