I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP, GET IN LINE...
(smacking lips)
(laughs)
THAT'LL PASS.
FOR SOME FLAT-OUT
KILLER SANDWICHES.
RIGHT ON, MAN!
IN AUSTIN, TEXAS...
(imitating Elmer Fudd)
BE VEWWY, VEWWY QUIET.
A SIDEWALK STAND...
LET'S HIT IT.
WITH A SIMPLE MENU...
COW, CHICKEN, PIG, SHRIMP.
THAT'S A WOLF
IN SHEEP'S CLOTHING.
AH, THAT'S THE BOMB, DUDE.
SERIOUSLY.
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
SPONGE, PLEASE. (laughs)
A GOURMET FOOD TRUCK...
LOOK AT THAT.
PARKED INSIDE A DIVE BAR.
NO WAY.
I MEAN, COME ON.
YOU SEE IT EVERY DAY.
SOMEBODY'S A WINNER.
(cheering)
(sizzling)
AND IN DALLAS, TEXAS...
(both laughing)
A SIDE-OF-THE-ROAD JOINT...
NICE!
WORKING DIFFERENT
TECHNIQUES...
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA!
TO BUILD THE PERFECT BURGER.
DON'T JUST GIVE ME
A GOOD THESIS
AND A NICE OUTLINE.
GIVE ME A FANTASTIC
CONCLUSION.
CONCLUSION. EXACTLY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE ON SOUTH LAMAR,
ONE OF THE BUSY THOROUGHFARES
HERE IN AUSTIN, TEXAS.
I'M ABOUT A MILE AND A HALF
AWAY FROM SIXTH STREET.
WHY AM I HERE?
I HEAR THERE'S THIS
FUNKY LITTLE BAR,
AND OUTSIDE THERE'S
A FOOD TRUCK
THAT IS ROCKIN'
THE SANDWICH SCENE!
THIS IS LUKE'S INSIDE OUT!
THIS IS THE BEST FOOD TRUCK
IN TOWN.
YOU CAN SIT OUTSIDE. YOU COULD
GO SIT IN THE BAR IF YOU'D LIKE.
THAT'D BE GIBSON'S BAR,
LITERALLY RIGHT NEXT DOOR.
THEY GIVE YOU A PLACE
TO PARK IT,
YOU GIVE THEM A SERVICE--
PACKAGE DEAL.
IT'S A GREAT DEAL.
(woman) LUKE'S VERY CREATIVE
WITH HIS MENU, AND--
IS CREATIVE A NICE WAY
OF SAYING "CRAZY"?
YEAH!
CRAZY ENOUGH THAT AFTER 27
YEARS IN THE CATERING BUSINESS,
LUKE BIBBY AND HIS WIFE TRACY
WENT AFTER HIS CHILDHOOD DREAM.
I WAS, UH, ABOUT 9 YEARS OLD
WHEN I WAS STANDING IN FRONT OF
THE MICROWAVE MAKING SANDWICHES,
AND I ALWAYS WANTED
TO HAVE A SANDWICH SHOP.
AND WE FOUND THIS LOCATION
UNDERNEATH THAT TREE, AND...
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
TO PEOPLE
THE TYPE OF FOOD
THAT YOU'RE MAKING?
WHAT COMES OUT OF LUKE'S HEAD.
YOU THINK OF IT, IT CAN
COME OUT ON A SANDWICH?
OH, YEAH.
I'VE HAD EVERYTHING
FROM OXTAIL TO DUCK.
THIS IS THE RABBIT SANDWICH.
THE KOREAN RABBIT.
TATER TOTS, KIMCHI,
AND SHREDDED BULGOGI RABBIT.
(imitating Elmer Fudd)
BE VEWWY, VEWWY QUIET.
I'M COOKING WABBIT.
(laughs)
A RABBIT IS OFTEN FOUND HERE
IN THE GREATER AUSTIN AREA?
IT CERTAIN-WY IS.
LET'S HIT IT.
WHAT ARE WE PUTTING ON HERE?
BULGOGI MARINADE.
IT'S A KOREAN BARBECUE SAUCE.
MARINATE OVERNIGHT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON THE GRIDDLE
TO SEAR IT OFF.
OKAY. SEAR YOUR HARE.
WE'LL DO THE ONIONS FIRST.
CUT THOSE IN HALF.
THIS IS JUST TO PROTECT
THE, UH,
RABBIT FROM THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAN.
GARLIC.
SODA.
DIET.
WATCHING EVERY CALORIE.
GONNA COVER IT.
JUST GONNA BRAISE THERE
ON TOP OF THE GRIDDLE
FOR A COUPLE HOURS,
UNTIL SHE'S TENDER AND WE CAN
PULL HER OFF THE BONE.
WHAT ARE WE ON TO, BROTHER?
GONNA MAKE SOME KIMCHI.
I AM A KIMCHI JUNKIE.
GOT A HALF A HEAD
OF NAPA CABBAGE
THAT'S JUST BEEN SALTED,
AND IT LEACHED OUT
ALL THE WATER.
GOT IT.
GOT SOME RED CHILI PASTE.
FISH SAUCE.
A LITTLE SALT, A LITTLE SUGAR,
SOME DASHI--
I THINK IT'S FISH FOOD.
LET ME SEE THIS.
OH, BONITO STOCK.
FISH STOCK, FISH FOOD.
AHH. WHATEVER IT TAKES.
A LITTLE RED CHILI FLAKES.
MIX THIS ALL TOGETHER.
GONNA ADD CARROTS.
GREEN ONION. SOME APPLE.
LITTLE BIT OF RED JALAPEÑO.
NOW THIS MARINADE.
NOW WE TAKE THIS
AND WEIGH IT DOWN
IN THE REFRIGERATOR.
(sizzling)
WE TAKE...
PULLED RABBIT MEAT.
(clatters)
CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
SOME OF THAT BRAISING LIQUID.
(sizzling continues)
GRIDDLED FRENCH BREAD.
OF COURSE A LITTLE PARMESAN.
I COULD JUST EAT
THE KIMCHI.
ONCE THIS IS GOOD AND HOT...
(both) TATER TOTS.
GRIDDLED BREAD.
RABBIT!
A LITTLE KIMCHI.
THIS IS SOME KOREA CHOP.
OH!
A LITTLE SZECHUAN
CHILI PASTE.
KETCHUP AND...
SRIRACHA?
MM, I CAN'T TELL YOU THE REST.
WHY, OR YOU HAVE TO
KILL ME?
A1.
(crunches)
OH, THAT'S THE BOMB, DUDE.
SERIOUSLY.
THIS IS BANANAS.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
(mouth full) THE LUSCIOUSNESS
OF THE RABBIT--
IT'S GOT A RICH FLAVOR TO IT.
I LOVE BANH MI SANDWICHES.
THAT'S AT LEAST IN THE TOP FIVE
I'VE EVER HAD.
IT'S THE MOST UNIQUE
SANDWICH I'VE EVER HAD.
I LOVE THE ORIGINALITY
OF LUKE'S.
EVERYTHING'S NAMED
BASED ON THE MEAT THAT'S IN IT.
(Luke) COW, CHICKEN,
PIG, SHRIMP.
COULD YOU JUST DO ME A FAVOR
AND JUST DO
EITHER THE SOUND
OR THE SHAPE OF THE ANIMAL,
JUST SO I CAN HAVE
A BETTER INTERPRETATION?
BAWK-BAWK, OINK-OINK,
MOO, MOO.
THE SHRIMP DOESN'T MAKE
MUCH NOISE.
BUT IT MAKES
A KILLER SANDWICH.
(Luke) AND THIS IS THE SHRIMP.
IT HAS BLUE CHEESE
AND APPLE SLICES
AND ROSEMARY.
HERE'S THE SHRIMP.
INTO THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
WE'RE GONNA LEAVE SOME OF THEM
WHOLE. COUPLE OF WHOLE EGGS.
CORN STARCH.
CHIPOTLE PEPPER. ROSEMARY.
INTO THE FOOD PROCESSOR WE GO.
WE'RE GONNA PULSE THIS UP.
(whirring)
OKAY.
SO IN GOES THE MIXTURE.
THE REST OF THE SHRIMPS.
SO THE SHRIMP ARE GONNA
HOLD TOGETHER
IN THE MIXTURE OF SHRIMP?
GET ON IN THERE.
JUST FOLD IT TOGETHER. THEN WE
PORTION IT INTO 6-OUNCE PATTIES
AND WE PUT IT IN THE FRIDGE
OVERNIGHT.
LET IT ALL TIGHTEN UP,
KINDA CONGEAL.
IT DOES.
NEXT UP WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE BLUE GOO.
TAKE A LITTLE BIT
OF WHOLE-GRAIN DIJON.
BLUE CHEESE. MAYONNAISE.
TEXAS HONEY WITH SOME
SHISHITO PEPPERS STEEPED IN IT.
REALLY?
MM.
I LOVE SHISHITOS.
MMM.
THERE'S THE BLUE GOO.
IN THIS SALAD, WE TOSS IN
THE BABY SPINACH.
SLICED RED ONION.
GRANNY SMITH APPLE.
FOR THE BLUE GOO.
NOW WE COOK THE SHRIMP.
PUT IT ON THE YE OLD GRIDDLE.
YE OLD GRIDDLE?
MM-HMM.
A LITTLE MANTEQUILLA.
BUTTER.
(sizzling)
IT'S IN THE SHAPE
OF THE SANDWICH.
PUT A LITTLE HAT ON IT
FOR A MINUTE.
THAT'S JUST GONNA SIT THERE
AND CRUST UP.
AND YOU'RE GONNA
TOAST THE BREAD?
WE PUT DOWN A LITTLE
PARMESAN CHEESE
TO DRIVE THE NATIVES
CRAZY OUTSIDE.
THE NATIVE AUSTINITES.
THAT'S GONNA BE A GOOD ONE.
I CAN JUST TELL. LOOK AT HER.
LOOKS WEIRD.
YEAH.
IT'S NOT GONNA FALL
ON YOUR LAP, THOUGH.
RIGHT ON, MAN!
I LIKE THE WAY IT'S GOING.
TO THE BREAD.
NEVER SEEN A SHRIMP PATTY
LIKE THIS.
IT'S CRAZY.
HA HA!
BLUE GOO.
THE REVEAL.
(crunches)
(mouth full) OF THE SANDWICHES
I'VE HAD ON TRIPLE "D"--
I'VE HAD SOME CRAZY ONES--
IT'S A LOT CRAZIER.
YOU GOT GREAT TEXTURE.
LOVE THE APPLE.
LOVE THE CRUNCH.
LOVE THE ONION CRUNCH.
THE BLUE CHEESE DOES KINDA
TAKE THE LEAD.
REALLY GOOD BREAD.
SO IT IS
SHRIMPY VON SHRIMPNESS.
CULINARY TERM.
THAT IS THE SHRIMP.
AND HE IS THE LUKE.
AND I AM THE GUY.
(laughs)
(mouth full) THERE'S
ONLY ONE PROBLEM.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
HAVING TO SEE METALLICA PLAY
IN A 10x17.
YOU'RE JUST TOO BIG
OF A BAND
TO PLAY
IN SUCH A SMALL ARENA.
NICE.
(mouth full) AWESOME, DUDE.
I'D BUY ALL YOUR ALBUMS.
(laughing)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA.
HEY, HAVE YOU HEARD THE ONE
WHERE THE FANCY FOOD TRUCK
WALKS INTO A DIVE BAR?
ROASTED LAMB SANDWICH.
(mouth full) THAT IS
THE SANDWICH OF SANDWICHES.
THIS TIME, IT AIN'T NO JOKE.
♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN MINNEAPOLIS
IN THE NORDEAST--
OR THE NORTHEAST,
AS THEY CALL IT--
JUST CATTY-CORNER FROM THE OLD
GRAIN BELT BREWERY.
NOW WHAT DO WE GOT? YEP.
ANOTHER TACO TRUCK
BACKIN' UP TO A BAR.
BUT BECAUSE WE'RE
IN MINNEAPOLIS,
THEY LIKE TO CALL IT
A LOBSTER TRUCK PULLIN' UP
TO A DIVE.
THIS IS SMACK SHACK
1029 BAR.
THANK YOU.
(man) THE FOOD TRUCK
IS USUALLY
ON 7th AND MARQUETTE
IN DOWNTOWN MINNEAPOLIS.
BUT WHEN THE TRUCK HIT
MAX CAPACITY...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CHEF JOSH THOMA
NEEDED ANOTHER OPTION...
SO HE TURNED TO HIS BUDDY
TROY OLSON.
(cheering)
THEY WANTED TO BRING LOBSTER
INTO THE BAR.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE CRAZY.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU'RE A BAR.
GOT IT.
STARTED AS A LOBSTER TRUCK.
YOU GOT IT.
YOU USE SOME OF THE KITCHEN
AS A HOME BASE,
RUN THE SMACK SHACK,
ALL MAKING GREAT FOOD,
SERVE IT TO THE BAR.
YOU GOT IT.
PACKAGE DEAL!
SOMEBODY'S A WINNER.
(mouths word)
(cheering)
EVERYTHING'S MADE
FROM SCRATCH?
YEAH. IT'S--IT'S REAL FOOD.
HI. LOBSTER ROLL FOR YOU.
THE LOBSTER ROLL
IS MY FAVORITE.
SHRIMP PO' BOY IS UP.
SHRIMP PO' BOY IS DELICIOUS.
BUT IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR MORE TURF THAN SURF...
HERE'S YOUR
ROASTED LAMB SANDWICH.
DON'T WORRY,
THEY GOT YOU COVERED.
THE LAMB IS VERY TENDER.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WE GOT OUR BONE-IN
LEG OF LAMB.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUT
THE SHANK HERE. SAVE THAT GUY.
YOU KNOW THEY'LL COME IN
BONED OUT.
YEAH, BUT THEN I DON'T
GET THE BONES.
THE BONE IS THE KEY
TO THE JUICE.
MAKES THE STOCK.
WE'RE GONNA DO THYME.
WE HAVE ROSEMARY.
GARLIC. PUT A LITTLE
CANOLA ON THERE.
THIS IS THE MESSY PART.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
THERE WE GO.
WE'RE GONNA TIE A LITTLE
SURGEON'S KNOT HERE.
SPONGE, PLEASE. (laughs)
BONED, ROLLED, AND TIED.
THIS SITS OVERNIGHT.
THEN WE SALT AND PEPPER IT.
THEN IT GOES IN.
200 WE GO, ABOUT 4 TO 5 HOURS.
WHAT ARE WE ON TO?
NEXT WE'RE MAKING
SAFFRON AIOLI.
GO FOR GARLIC.
SOME SAFFRON TEA.
IT'S IN BLOOM.
A LITTLE WARM WATER.
BIG SAFFRON ON THAT.
(whirring)
THEN WE GO LEMON AIOLI.
YOU MAKE THIS YOURSELF?
WE DO, YEAH.
GO BIG.
A LITTLE PULSE.
BIT OF HARISSA IN THERE.
HARISSA.
THAT'S KIND OF LIKE A CURRY
OR A SALSA.
JUST THAT BEAUTIFUL ORANGE--
THAT HUE.
(whirring)
PROBABLY SHOULD TASTE THAT.
(smacking lips)
(laughter)
THAT'LL PASS.
NICE.
COOLED DOWN, READY TO ROLL.
WE SNIP, SNIP, SNIP.
THAT IS AWESOME!
(smacks lips) AHH!
HERE WE GO.
RIGHT DOWN THE MIDDLE.
THERE.
LOOK AT THAT!
RIGHT THERE.
LOW AND SLOW.
SLICE SUPER THIN.
(mutters) ALL RIGHT.
(mouth full) YO,
I'VE HAD SOME GREAT LAMB.
THAT LOW AND SLOW
AT THE 200 JUST BROKE IT DOWN.
OUTSTANDING.
I MEAN, STUPID IN FLAVOR.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S A SANDWICH?
PICTURE THAT.
(speaks indistinctly)
I'LL PICTURE IT IN A SECOND.
MAKE IT A REALITY.
YOU GOT THE AU JUS WORKING.
I MAKE SURE THAT I KEEP THAT FAT
RIGHT IN THE STOCK
SO THAT WHEN I PULL IT UP,
I GET A LITTLE BIT OF LAMB FAT.
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT SIT
FOR ONE SEC.
OKAY.
FIRST WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO IS
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR HARISSA.
OHH, HO!
THEN WE GO RIGHT ONTO
THE SANDWICH, RIGHT FROM HERE.
WE GOT OUR FENNEL SEED
SLAW.
FENNEL ROCKS IT!
WE GOT OUR SAFFRON AIOLI
RIGHT HERE,
AND WE GO JUST LIKE THIS.
YOU SERVE THIS WITH AN AU JUS?
WE DO. RIGHT HERE.
LOOK AT THAT!
DUNKIFY.
(mouth full) IT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
THAT'S THE DEFINITION
OF "STUPID" IN FLAVOR TOWN.
"STUPID" IN THE GOOD WAY.
ROASTS OFF AT 200 DEGREES
FOR 4 HOURS.
STUPID!
THIS HAS GOT TO BE
IN THE TOP GREATEST
LAMB SANDWICHES I'VE HAD.
(mouth full) SO GOOD.
OH, MY GOSH!
THAT IS THE SANDWICH
OF SANDWICHES.
COMING UP...
LOBSTER BATTLE ROYALE!
I GOTTA PICK UP THAT TOWEL...
(man) THE LOBSTER MAC & CHEESE,
IT'S LIKE PERFECTION.
'CAUSE I AIN'T DONE
AT THE SHACK.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
♪♪
YEAH, IT'S A GREAT DAY
IN THE NORDEAST SECTION
OF MINNEAPOLIS,
BUT LOOKS...
(chuckles) ARE DECEIVING.
'CAUSE TUCKED INSIDE
THE 1029 BAR,
YOU GOT THE SMACK SHACK...
BACON MAC'S GOING UP.
SERVING UP
SCRATCH-MADE DISHES
BUILT TO KEEP YOU
WARM INSIDE,
ALL SERVED UP
IN A NEIGHBORHOOD BAR.
YOU DO CALL IT
A DIVE BAR?
YEAH. OH, YEAH.
WITH PRIDE, I'D SAY.
(cheering)
IT'S LIKE AN ADULT DISNEYLAND.
PULL TABS AND ALL.
YOU EVER WON ANYTHING
ON THAT?
NO.
YEAH. ME, EITHER.
BUT THE REAL JACKPOT HERE
IS THE MENU.
SMACK SHACK IS KNOWN FOR,
UH, VARIOUS LOBSTER DISHES.
LOBSTER ROLL'S UP.
AM I IN, LIKE, A LOBSTER
AREA OF MINNEAPOLIS, OR...
I DON'T THINK THERE'S
A LOBSTER AREA OF MINNESOTA.
YOU'D SWEAR THAT IF YOU WENT
OUTSIDE, YOU'D SEE THE OCEAN.
THE LOBSTER MAC & CHEESE IS--
IT'S LIKE PERFECTION.
SUNDAY, SUNDAY, SUNDAY!
LOBSTER BATTLE ROYALE!
(bell clangs)
WAH!
FRESH LIVE MAINE LOBSTERS
ALL THE TIME FOR MAC AND CHEESE.
YOU GOT IT.
TINY PORTION?
SNAPPY TIME PORTION.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THAT
IN THE FLAVOR TOWN DICTIONARY.
SO WE'RE GONNA DROP THESE GUYS
IN--SALTED BOILING WATER.
THOSE ARE GONNA BE DOWN
FOR NINE MINUTES.
JUST PULL 'EM OUT,
HIT 'EM IN THE ICE BATH.
TAKE THESE GUYS OUT,
CHILLED DOWN.
SNAP 'EM OPEN JUST LIKE THIS.
I GIVE 'EM A LITTLE TWIST.
GIVE IT A PRESS.
POP THESE GUYS RIGHT OPEN.
(shell cracking)
LIGHTLY POACHED LOBSTER MEAT.
(mouth full) THAT'LL BE OKAY.
BE ABLE TO WORK WITH THAT.
AND WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR CHEESE SAUCE.
START WITH OUR WHITE WINE.
LET THAT REDUCE
FOR ABOUT 10 MINUTES.
SOME CREAM.
HEAVY CRÈME.
GO ANOTHER 10 MINUTES.
LET IT REDUCE.
SOME BUTTER.
GONNA MAKE BASICALLY
KIND OF A BEURRE BLANC--
AN ITALIAN FONDUTA.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR GRATED
FONTINA CHEESE.
TALEGGIO CHEESE.
(whistles)
ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
AND IF YOU HAVEN'T HAD
TALEGGIO BEFORE,
IT'S KIND OF GOT
THE CONSISTENCY...
A LITTLE BIT LIKE BRIE.
BUT STINKIER.
(French accent) LE PARFUM.
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR
CHEESE SAUCE, JUST LIKE THAT.
WE GOT OUR FONTINA,
GOT OUR WHITE WINE.
DUDE, THAT'S FONDUE.
THAT'S FONDUTA.
THE ELBOW RIGATE.
THE RIDGES ON THE OUTSIDE
OF THE PASTA,
WHICH HELP THE SAUCE
HOLD ON TO IT.
WE'RE GONNA DROP OUR PASTA.
WE GOT SOME SWEET CORN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR LOBSTER.
SOLID 3 OUNCES.
NO WAY! THIS IS HOW
YOU MAKE IT EACH TIME?
EACH TIME.
TAKE IT OUT, GIVE IT A SHAKE.
GOES RIGHT IN.
GET THE TOSS, TOSS, TOSS.
I'M WITH YOU.
SO YOU GOT IT?
NOT GOING ANYWHERE,
TRUST ME.
ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS GONNA BE
RICH A LA RICH.
CHOPPED ITALIAN PARSLEY.
SOME PANKO BREAD CRUMBS.
TOASTED PANKO.
THAT'S IT.
AND SERVED
WITH A PLASTIC FORK.
YOU PUT THE "K" IN "CLASS,"
MY FRIEND.
(laughs) YOU GOT IT.
(mouth full) MMM!
(pounding wall)
(whispers) HAD TO GET THAT OUT.
WOW, THAT'S GOOD.
(mouth full) INCREDIBLY
RICH SAUCE.
SO MUCH REAL LOBSTER
FLAVOR TO IT.
AND THEN THE KICKER FOR ME
IS THE LITTLE SWEET CORN.
AND SOME OF THE PANKO
BREAD CRUMBS
SO YOU GET THAT
LITTLE CRUNCH.
GET THAT CRUNCH.
(mouth full) RIDICULOUS.
GREAT JOB.
THANK YOU.
GUY'S THE MACK.
AS IN "LOBSTER MAC."
THE LOBSTER MAC & CHEESE--
LOVE IT.
THIS IS THE BEST FOOD. I DON'T
CARE WHERE YOU GO IN TOWN.
SO YOU--
THIS IS...
IT'S THE BEST.
IN A FUNKY DIVE BAR?
MAKES SENSE.
SEE, I WISH I HAD THIS
IN MY NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU WANNA COME,
YOU WANNA HANG OUT,
YOU GET SOMETHING TO EAT--
CAN'T BEAT IT.
NICE JOB.
AWESOME, MY BROTHER.
YOU BET.
(rattling)
(spray hissing)
(laughter)
UP NEXT...
(foreign accent) YOU LIKE,
A-DISCO DANCING,
A-TABLE TENNIS,
AND A-MELT THE CHEESE.
WE'RE HEADED TO DALLAS,
TEXAS...
PRIME-TIME, BADASS BURGER.
WHERE ONE BURGER JOINT'S
LASER FOCUS...
JUST BURGERS?
IT'S THE ONLY CHORDS
I KNOW.
HAS GOT ME ALL FIRED UP.
THAT'S CALLED
THE LOVE MASTER.
(mouth full) I THINK MY JAW JUST
LOCKED UP WHEN I ATE THAT.
(laughter)
♪♪
SO I'M ABOUT 2 MILES NORTHWEST
OF DOWNTOWN DALLAS
AT A FAMOUS INTERSECTION
THAT WAS CALLED MAPLE AND MOTOR.
WELL, TIMES HAVE CHANGED,
AND THEY RENAMED IT.
IT'S NOT MAPLE AND MOTOR.
IT'S MAPLE AND...
MEDICAL DISTRICT DRIVE?
DEFINITELY NOT THE SNAZZY,
PIZZAZZY NAME THAT IT WAS.
ANYHOW, ONE DUDE
AIN'T LETTIN' IT GO,
AND HE'S PRESERVING THE NAME
BY SERVING BURGERS AND BEERS.
THIS IS MAPLE & MOTOR.
(sizzling)
BURGER ALL THE WAY PINK.
B.L.T.
THIS IS, WITHOUT A DOUBT
ABOUT IT,
THE VERY BEST BURGER
IN THE METROPLEX.
JACK'S A MAGICIAN BACK THERE.
THAT'D BE OWNER
JACK PERKINS,
A FORMER HIGH SCHOOL
ENGLISH TEACHER
WHO SWAPPED HIS PENCIL
FOR A SPATULA IN '09.
NOW THE DUDE'S GOT A MASTER'S
IN BURGEROLOGY.
YOU ONLY MAKE BURGERS,
DON'T YOU?
THAT'S IT.
JUST BURGERS?
IT'S THE ONLY CHORDS
I KNOW,
AND IT'S AS FAST
AS I CAN PLAY 'EM.
AND HIS FINGERS ARE FLYIN',
FLIPPIN' 600 A DAY
FOR A LINE
THAT'S OUT THE DOOR.
CHEESEBURGER ALL THE WAY.
JACK'S GOT SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE.
COWBOY STYLE
WITH CHILI, CHEESE, AND ONION.
JACKED UP, WHICH IS
THE WAY I EAT IT.
CHILI, CHEESE, ONION,
TEXAS TOAST, FRIED EGG.
(Guy) MMM!
ALL RIGHT, WHAT'S THE NUMBER-ONE
BURGER ON THE MENU?
BACON CHEESEBURGER WITH,
UH, FRESH GRILLED JALAPEÑOS.
HIT IT.
WHAT WE DO IS IT'S A COMBINATION
OF THE SHOULDER CLAW--
THE CHUCK--GOING WITH
THE BRISKET.
IT'S, UH, 70/30.
WHAT'S GONNA END UP--
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA.
YOU WANT IT FAT.
SERIOUSLY?
MM-HMM.
SO YOU'RE FORTIFYING WITH
THE FAT AND THE FLAVOR
RIGHT OFF THE BAT. OKAY.
RIGHT.
WHAT SIZE PATTY
ARE WE MAKING?
BETWEEN 7 AND 8 OUNCES.
IT'S A BIG BURGER.
IT IS A BIG BURGER.
MMM.
THE IDEA WITH THE BALL IS,
IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA--
IT'S GONNA SIT HERE UNTIL WE
GET A LITTLE POOL OF JUICE.
SO WE'RE WAITING
FOR A JUICY POOL?
YEAH.
OKAY, WHEN WE GET A POOL,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE SPATULA,
PUT IT ON TOP...
ALL RIGHT.
ALONG WITH A STEAK WEIGHT,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
ROCK IT CLOSED.
SO IT'S SO HOT THAT
THAT FAT'S COOKING DOWN--
THE FAT'S ALMOST
FRYING THE MEAT.
BUILDS A REALLY NICE CRUST.
BE A LITTLE MOIST IN THE CENTER.
HE'S GONNA FLIP IT
AND GENERATE THE SAME THING
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
ABSOLUTELY.
NICE!
PERFECT, RIGHT?
JALAPEÑOS.
WE'RE JUST ABOUT READY.
CHEDDAR.
GRAB THE BUN.
(sizzling)
LETTUCE ON THE BOTTOM
TO PROTECT THE BOTTOM BUN.
THE BACON.
JALAPEÑOS.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT. BUN ON TOP.
IT'S LIKE,
DON'T JUST GIVE ME
A GOOD THESIS
AND A NICE OUTLINE.
FOLLOW THROUGH, SON.
EXACTLY.
GIVE ME A FANTASTIC
CONCLUSION.
CONCLUSION. EXACTLY.
TEACHER TALK.
MMM!
(mouth full) I WILL TELL YOU,
THAT'S A STRAIGHT-UP
DELICIOUS,
PRIME-TIME,
BADASS BURGER.
THANK YOU.
AND IT FIRST STARTS
WITH THE MEAT.
COOKING IT HOT--
FLAT-TOP HOT.
PUTTIN' THAT CRUST ON IT.
LITTLE BIT OF BACON--
REALLY GOOD BACON.
MMM.
BUT THE BUN'S
GOTTA BE SOFT
AND DISAPPEAR WITH A NICE CRUST
THAT HOLDS IT TOGETHER.
LIKE AN EDIBLE VESSEL
TO GET IT INTO YOUR FACE HOLE.
MMM!
ALL RIGHT, I HAVE
A BACON CHEESEBURGER
WITH GRILLED JALAPEÑOS.
(man) AMAZING.
I GET THAT A LOT.
(mouth full) CHEERS.
ONE BURGER, ONE RING.
THIS JOINT'S EVEN INSPIRING ME
TO ADD ONE MORE TEXAS-SIZED
CREATION TO THE MENU
FOR MY BRO,
BIG-TIME TEXAS CHEF TIM LOVE.
I WANT TO MAKE HIM
SOMETHING SPECIAL.
OKAY.
SO I'M GONNA KIND OF
CONCOCT UP A LITTLE BURGER.
CAN I GET FREE RANGE TO...
YEAH, YOU'RE IN.
KINDA GO AFTER IT THE WAY
I WANT TO GO AFTER IT?
MAKE WHAT YOU WANT. SURE.
KEEP UP NOW.
DOUBLE PATTIES...
(sizzling)
GRILLED ONIONS,
AND JALAPEÑOS.
I SAY WE TAKE A PIECE
OF THIS BOLOGNA.
CRISPY DELICIOUSNESS.
GRAB SOME BACON.
WHAT'S THIS? WHAT'S THIS,
YOU SAY? IT'S BRISKET.
LITTLE SCOOP OF CHILI.
LITTLE CHILI RIGHT ON THERE.
COUPLE, UH, PIECES
OF CHEDDAR.
THROW A LITTLE DOME ON THAT.
LOOK AT THAT CHEESE, HUH?
VERY NICE. YEAH.
(foreign accent)
THAT'S A MELTY-MELTY.
THAT'S WHAT I TALK ABOUT.
YOU LIKE A-DISCO DANCING,
A-TABLE TENNIS,
AND A-MELT THE CHEESE.
(normal voice) SO THERE WE'VE
GOT ONE OF THE BRISKET CHILI
HODAD TRIPLE MELTS
GOING RIGHT UP.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
BLACKENED BOLOGNA.
WE GOT THE BRISKET IN THERE,
A POUND OF BURGER,
AND THEN THE CHILI.
AND TOP HER OFF WITH JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF BACON,
SOME JALAPEÑOS.
THAT RIGHT THERE--
THAT'S CALLED THE LOVE MASTER.
(both laughing)
ORDER UP!
LOOK AT IT.
YOU SAID YOU WERE GONNA
MAKE ME A BIG ONE.
DO IT.
(laughs)
YOU GONNA GET IN THERE
WITH ME?
I MIGHT. WE--WE'LL SEE
WHAT HAPPENS.
I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY--
OH, LOOK AT THAT!
WITH A NICE CUT!
(Jack) OH, THAT'S SPECTACULAR.
THAT'S A PRETTY
GOOD-LOOKING BURGER.
HUH? ALL RIGHT,
TAKE FIRST BITE.
FIRST BLOOD, RAMBO.
ONE, TWO, THREE...
(laughter)
(mouth full)
THAT WAS IMPRESSIVE.
(mouth full) MM-HMM.
(laughing)
I THINK MY JAW JUST LOCKED UP
WHEN I ATE THAT.
(Jack laughs)
MINE JUST SNAPPED OPEN
LIKE AN ANACONDA.
(all laughing)
WANT A BITE?
NO, NO, I'M GOOD!
(laughter)
CHEESEBURGER PLAIN WITH MUSTARD,
PICKLES, AND KETCHUP.
YOU SEE ALL TYPES OF PEOPLE
COME IN HERE--
SUITS AND TIES,
GUYS IN T-SHIRTS AND SHORTS.
SO IT FITS
EVERY KIND OF PERSON,
BUT IN A VERY, VERY
RELAXED ATMOSPHERE.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS ROAD TRIP.
BUT DON'T WORRY.
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ONE "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(mouth full) 'CAUSE IF YOU--
YOU GET
LIKE A COUPLE--
LIKE COAT HANGERS...
(laughing)
AND YOU COULD JUST--
JUST GET IT HERE, THEN...
(stomps foot)
WITH--LIKE WITH A FORK
TO YOUR--
TRY TIGHTENING UP
YOUR GAME.
(laughs)