I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I'M SO HAPPY RIGHT NOW,
I COULD KISS YOU. (kisses)
(laughs)
THE CAMARO IS LOADED
WITH AN ALL-STAR LINEUP.
YOU JUST SHOW ME THE JOINTS,
I'LL BE HERE.
IN GEORGETOWN, TEXAS...
MATTHEW, JUMP IN.
A BIG-TIME CAFE...
KING RANCH CASSEROLE.
WHERE MY BRO McCONAUGHEY...
YOU JUST JUMPED RIGHT IN
AND TOOK THE CORNER?
YOU GOT THREE MORE.
(laughter)
IS KICKIN' BACK
THE KILLER ENCHILADA.
"CASHILADA."
THAT'S LIKE
TEXAS COMFORT FOOD.
AND IN MINNEAPOLIS...
WEST COAST!
MINNESOTA!
THE PIZZA PARLOR FIRING UP
CRAZY COMBOS...
THIS IS GONNA
BLOW YOUR MIND.
THAT HAVE GOT ME
CALLING IN A RINGER...
THIS IS MY BROTHER
FROM ANOTHER MOTHER.
WHO KNOWS A LITTLE SOMETHING...
DON'T GO THROUGH THE YOLK!
ABOUT ADVENTUROUS EATIN'.
THAT MIGHT BE ONE
OF THE ONLY WAYS
I THINK I MIGHT BRANCH OUT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS..."
(tires screech)
"AND DIVES."
♪♪
MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA'S
KNOWN FOR A LOT OF THINGS--
GENERAL MILLS,
MALL OF AMERICA,
OF COURSE THE VIKINGS.
BUT DID YOU KNOW THEY HAVE
ONE OF THE ONLY
COPPER-COVERED, WOOD-FIRED
FRENCH PIZZA OVENS--
A LE PANYOL--
AT THIS PLACE,
WHERE THEY'RE
DOING OFF-THE-HOOK PIZZA?
THIS IS PIZZERIA LOLA.
(woman) ISLAND PIZZA.
ABOUT 30 SECONDS
ON THE LADY ZaZa.
HAWAII PIE-O.
(woman) SWEET ITALIAN.
SUNNYSIDE PIZZA,
ORDER UP.
A LOT OF UNUSUAL FLAVORS.
MY SHA-RONI! UP.
I'M A CHICAGO BOY.
I KNOW MY PIZZA.
THIS IS RIGHT UP THERE
WITH THE BEST IN CHICAGO.
THERE'S ATTITUDE
IN EVERY SINGLE PIZZA.
SLICED AND SERVED UP
BY OWNER ANN KIM,
WHO GREW UP LEARNING TO COOK
FROM HER KOREAN GRANDMA,
BEFORE DISCOVERING ANOTHER
PASSION A LITTLE LATER IN LIFE.
MARGHERITA UP!
I LIVED IN NEW YORK
FOR SEVEN YEARS.
SPENT MOST OF IT WHILE I WAS
IN COLLEGE EATING PIZZA.
NOW SHE'S BACK HOME
IN MINNESOTA,
TOPPING ARTISAN CRUST
WITH SAVORY INGREDIENTS,
LIKE TRUFFLE CHEESE
ON THE FORAGER,
ALMONDS ON THE XERXES,
OR PROSCIUTTO AND ARUGULA
ON THE IOWAN.
♪♪
BUT SHE'S ALSO GOT HER EYE
ON THE FM DIAL
AND ROCKIN' A CLASSIC.
(Ann) HERE'S YOUR MY SHA-RONI!
I JUST KIND OF LIKE
A MEAT OVERLOAD.
(hums "My Sharona")
IS THAT WHERE IT'S FROM?
YEAH.
♪♪
HOW ARE WE GONNA
START THE DOUGH?
WE MAKE A POOLISH.
FOR ME, IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE DOUGH...
OKAY.
AND THE SLOW RISE
AND THE FERMENTATION.
LET'S SEE IT.
FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA DO
IS ADD SOME WATER.
A TEENY BIT OF YEAST.
AND THEN THE FLOUR.
NOW WE MIX THIS UP?
YEP.
FOR ABOUT FIVE OR SIX
MINUTES,
UNTIL IT'S NICELY
INCORPORATED, NO LUMPS,
AND THEN WE LET IT SIT ABOUT
17 HOURS IN THE BASEMENT.
MAKE ONE FOR TODAY...
YEP.
AND WE'RE GONNA USE
FOR TOMORROW.
YEP. EXACTLY.
DIG IT.
OKAY, POOLISH IS READY.
YES.
AHH! IF THEY MADE COLOGNE...
(laughs)
THIS SHOULD BE THE GUY FIERI
BRAND OF COLOGNE.
EAU DE POO.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA DUMP
THE POOLISH IN LIKE THAT.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD
ITALIAN FLOUR,
AND THEN SOME MORE YEAST,
SOME COLOR WATER,
AND LAST, SOME ITALIAN
SEA SALT.
WE'RE GONNA LET THIS
PROOF UP?
YES.
AND NOW WE'LL MIX HER UP.
(whirring softly)
TEN MINUTES?
THE KEY IS TO MIX IT
JUST ENOUGH.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GET
THE GLUTENS
TOO STRETCHY AND TIGHT.
COVER IT UP, LET IT SIT
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
CUT IT INTO 9-OUNCE
DOUGHBALLS.
PUT IT INTO A DOUGH TRAY,
AND THEN PUT IT IN THE COOLER
OVERNIGHT.
SO THIS ISN'T A 24-HOUR DOUGH.
THIS IS A 48-HOUR DOUGH.
YEP. IT'S A 2-DAY PROCESS.
OH, SO IT'S GONNA HAVE
A REALLY NICE, YEASTY FLAVOR.
OH, YEAH.
I WANTED TO OPEN A BAKERY.
YEAH?
AND CALL IT
THE YEASTIE BOYS.
♪♪
I LIKE IT.
WEST COAST.
(laughs) MINNESOTA!
(laughs)
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING OUR HOUSE-MADE
FENNEL SAUSAGE.
WE HAVE GROUND
BERKSHIRE PORK.
MMM.
WE ADD TOASTED FENNEL SEED.
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC.
RED CHILI FLAKE.
SALT.
AND FRESHLY GROUND PEPPER,
WHICH WE GRIND OURSELVES,
OF COURSE.
YOU HAVE TO.
YEP. AND THEN--
SHE'S SAYING ALL THE THINGS--
IT'S LIKE MUSIC.
(laughs)
WE MASSAGE THE PORK.
THIS IS GONNA MAKE
A HAPPY PIZZA.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
FLATTEN IT OUT A LITTLE BIT.
400 DEGREES.
15, 20 MINUTES?
YEP.
GOT IT.
NEXT UP...
OUR HOUSE RED SAUCE.
START OFF WITH SOME FRESH-GROUND
CALIFORNIA TOMATOES.
STANISLAUS?
YES. HOW'D YOU GUESS?
(singsongy) I'M FROM CALI!
YEAH.
OH, YEAH. WEST SIDE!
AND THEN STANISLAUS
RED PEAR TOMATOES.
TOMATO PUREE. SALT.
DRIED BASIL.
DRIED OREGANO.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
A LITTLE BIT OF ONION POWDER.
WHISK HER UP.
I WISH I COULD GET SOME
OF THIS TO GO. NEXT UP?
LET'S MAKE A MY SHA-RONI!
NO THROW?
NO! THAT'S JUST FOR SHOW.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE CENTRIFUGAL
FORCE HAS ANY PLAY IN IT?
MAYBE, BUT, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS JUST A 9-INCH PIZZA.
OH, OKAY, WELL...
THE HOUSE RED SAUCE,
WISCONSIN.
MOZZARELLA. FENNEL SAUSAGE
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
NATURAL CASING PEPPERONI.
CARDIO BYPASS.
(laughs)
ADIOS.
STICK IT IN THE OVEN.
SO WE'RE RUNNING THE DECK
RIGHT AROUND--WHAT DO YOU SAY?
BETWEEN 550, 600.
OKAY.
YEAH. AND THEY COOK FAST.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WAIT LONG
FOR A PIZZA PIE HERE.
THROW A FINAL CRISP ON IT.
OH, YEAH. ALL RIGHT.
LOOK AT THAT RIGHT THERE.
(laughs) LOOK HOW THIN THAT IS.
MMM.
WE GOT THIS HEIRLOOM PORK
WITH THE REAL FAT IN IT
AND THE REAL FLAVOR.
AND THE FENNEL IS ROCKIN' THIS!
HA HA!
(laughs)
A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL SAY,
"OH, SAUSAGE AND PEPPERONI.
I'VE HAD THAT ALL THE TIME."
THIS IS WAY BEYOND YOUR EVERYDAY
PIZZA JOINT ON THE CORNER
SAUSAGE AND PEPPERONI.
YOU GOTTA TRY THIS ONE.
IT'S THE MOST HEIGHTENED,
DELICIOUS
PEPPERONI/SAUSAGE PIZZA
YOU'VE EVER HAD.
YOU'RE LIKE,
THIS IS WHAT PEPPERONI
IS SUPPOSED TO TASTE LIKE.
AND THEY HAVE A BUNCH OF PIZZAS
THAT ARE REALLY OUT THERE
AND INNOVATIVE.
INCLUDING A TRIBUTE
TO ANN'S DEEP KOREAN ROOTS.
THE LADY ZaZa.
LADY ZaZa?
(laughs) YEAH.
YOU THINK YOU'RE FUNNY,
DON'T YOU?
I WANT SOME SPICY HOT
LADY ZaZa.
(laughs)
YOU DO. YOU WILL.
YOU WILL.
OKAY. WHAT'S IN IT?
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S BRINE THE NAPA CABBAGE
FOR THE KIMCHI.
OH, MY GOSH.
I'M A KIMCHI JUNKIE.
THIS IS GONNA
BLOW YOUR MIND.
WE TAKE OUR NAPA CABBAGE.
WARM SALT WATER.
SOME KOREAN SEA SALT
IN THERE.
TRANSFER IT TO THIS BOWL.
YEP.
LETTING THE SALT WATER
SOAK ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
YEAH.
SO THEN AFTER WE DO THAT,
WE'LL JUST SPRINKLE
A LITTLE BIT MORE SALT
IN BETWEEN EACH LEAF.
THIS IS REALLY
HOW YOU DO IT?
YOU SIT HERE
AND SPRINKLE EACH LAYER?
YEAH.
THIS IS THE WAY
MY MOM TAUGHT ME,
AND I'M NOT GONNA
CHANGE IT UP.
ONCE ALL THE CABBAGE
IS BRINED,
WE'LL JUST LET IT SIT
IN THIS BOWL AGAIN.
JUST PULL OUT THE MOISTURE.
YES.
AND HOW LONG IS IT
GONNA SIT?
ABOUT THREE HOURS,
TILL IT GETS WILTED.
OKAY. THESE ARE SET
AND DONE, RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT. YEAH.
NEXT.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PASTE
THAT WE'RE GONNA PUT
ON THE KIMCHI.
START OFF WITH SOME
KOREAN CHILI POWDER...
MAGIC KOREAN CHILI FLAKES.
WHICH MY MOM
IMPORTS FOR US.
SOME FISH SAUCE.
CHOPPED SCALLION.
SOME BRINE SHRIMP.
(whistles)
FRESH GARLIC.
GARLIC.
FRESH GINGER.
A LITTLE BIT OF SUGAR.
MIX IT UP. ADD A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF THE BRINE WATER.
SOME OF THE SALTY WATER?
YEP.
CAME OFF OF THE CABBAGE?
YES.
OKAY. NOW SHOULD WE
TASTE IT, OR--
YEAH, YOU CAN TASTE IT
IF YOU WANT.
STRONG.
YEAH, IT'S FINE.
ONCE YOU FERMENT IT...
THAT'S AWESOME.
THE FLAVOR IS--
YEAH.
YOU GET THE SWEETNESS.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
SHRIMPY-NESS COMING THROUGH.
YOU GET SOME OF THE CHILI.
EACH LAYER?
YEAH.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE IT
AND STACK IT UP IN THIS...
YEP.
AND JUST LET IT SIT THERE
AND DO ITS WORK.
BEAUTY OF FERMENTATION
IS TIME WORKS ALL MAGIC.
HOW IMPORTANT IS KIMCHI
IN KOREAN CULTURE?
IT'S LIKE THE HAMBURGER.
IN KOREA, YOU'LL FIND THOUSANDS
OF YEARS OLD KIMCHI.
NO!
NO, I'M SERIOUS.
IT'S LIKE FINE WINE.
ALL RIGHT, NEXT UP?
OUR HOUSE-MADE
KOREAN SAUSAGE.
BERKSHIRE PORK.
AND SALT.
FRESH-GROUND PEPPER.
SUGAR.
FRESH-GROUND GINGER.
MMM.
GINGER SMELLS AWESOME.
ISN'T IT GREAT?
I'M A GINGER JUNKIE.
ARE YOU?
YEAH.
ME, TOO.
FRESH-GROUND GARLIC.
AND THEN FINALLY
SOME KOREAN CHILI.
AND MASSAGE THE INGREDIENTS
INTO THE PORK.
MASSAGE IT INTO THE PAN.
IT'S READY TO GO
AS A NICE TOPPING.
EXACTLY.
SO ALL OF THIS NOW--
NOW WE BUILD THE PIE.
YES.
LET'S ROCK 'N' ROLL.
ALL RIGHT.
ON THE BASE IS RED CALIFORNIA
PEAR TOMATOES.
SOME OF THIS KOREAN SAUSAGE.
THAT KIMCHI
THAT WE MADE EARLIER.
SERRANO PEPPERS.
FRESH SCALLION.
AND THEN WE FINISH IT OFF
WITH SESAME OIL.
CHICKEN IN THE OVEN.
YOU--YOU CALL IT
A PIZZA OVEN.
ME--I CALL IT
A WOOD-FIRED OVEN.
AN ARTIST IN MAINE
CREATED IT.
HOW MUCH WAS THE OVEN?
PROBABLY MORE THAN
THAT CAR OUT THERE.
REALLY?
YEAH.
I LIKE IT.
(laughs) YEAH.
YOU'VE GOT DIFFERENT HEATS
GOING ON.
SHE WON'T PUT THE PIZZA IN
ON THE SAME SPOT AGAIN.
IF SHE PUTS IT
RIGHT BACK THERE,
IT'S JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF A TEMPERATURE DROP,
AND THAT COULD MAKE
ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
THIS ONE'S JUST ABOUT DONE.
OH! YOU SHOULD SMELL IT!
THEN THE SOY CHILI GLAZE.
TOP IT OFF WITH TOASTED
BLACK AND WHITE SESAME SEEDS.
LOOK AT THAT!
(mouth full) MMM, HMM, HMM!
WOW! GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEET,
A LITTLE SALT.
YOU GOT SOME CRUNCH.
THERE'S ONIONS, A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SERRANO.
(mouth full) WHAT DO YOU GOT,
DRAGON SAUCE ON TOP?
(laughs)
(mouth full) OUT OF ALL
THE JOINTS WE'VE TRIED,
WITHOUT QUESTION,
THIS IS WAY UP THERE.
JUST DYNAMITE.
DEFINITELY A DIFFERENT TAKE
ON PIZZA.
IT'S A GREAT COMBINATION
OF THE KOREAN INFLUENCE
MELDING
WITH A REALLY GOOD PIZZA.
KIMCHI ON PIZZA?
THAT'S NOTHING!
TWO FARM-FRESH EGGS.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
DON'T GO THROUGH THE YOLK!
I GOT COMPANY.
(laughing)
I'LL BE YOU FOR A SECOND.
JUST GET THE HAIR OVER MY HEAD.
THIS IS OFF THE HOOK.
♪♪
WE'RE HERE AT PIZZERIA LOLA
IN SOUTHWEST MINNEAPOLIS,
A JOINT PULLING
SOME UNBELIEVABLE PIES
OUT OF A RARE PIZZA OVEN.
BUT THEY GOT ONE HERE
WITH A TOPPING
THAT, MAN,
EVERYONE IN FLAVOR TOWN KNOWS
I AM NOT A BIG FAN OF.
(record needle scratches)
IT'S GOT AN EGG ON TOP.
SUNNYSIDE PIZZA!
SO I FIGURED,
IF I'M GONNA STEP OUT OF
MY CULINARY COMFORT ZONE--
HA--I'M DRAGGING IN
ONE OF MINNEAPOLIS'
FAVORITE CULINARY
DAREDEVILS...
(laughs)
ANDREW ZIMMERN.
THIS IS MY BROTHER
FROM ANOTHER MOTHER,
AND I GOTTA SAY...
(kiss)
WHEN THIS GUY SAYS "LEGIT,"
IT IS TOO LEGIT TO QUIT.
(laughs)
I GOT A 6 1/2-YEAR-OLD-KID.
WE EAT PIZZA ALL THE TIME.
WE LIVE
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER,
AND IT'S VERY EXCITING.
I THINK MINNEAPOLIS IS
THE BEST-KEPT FOOD SECRET
IN THE COUNTRY.
SO WHAT DO WE CALL
THIS PIZZA AGAIN?
SUNNYSIDE.
YEP. (laughs)
EGG PIZZA.
OH, IT'S--I'M TELLING YOU
SOMETHING.
IT IS MAGICAL WHAT HAPPENS
BETWEEN A WOOD-BURNING OVEN,
THE LEEKS, AND THE CHEESE.
WAIT TILL--
SO LET ME GET WHAT--
GET WHAT YOU--
YEAH.
NICE STRETCH ON THE DOUGH.
9-OUNCE DOUGH.
10 INCHES WIDE.
WE WENT DOWN WITH A LITTLE
PARMESAN? WHAT--WHAT--
YEAH. IT'S PECORINO ROMANO.
SOME PECORINO ROMANO, OKAY.
IMPORTED.
SO A NICE LITTLE SALTY CHEESE.
YEP.
THEN WE GO DOWN WITH SOME LEEKS,
AND WHAT WAS THE CREAM?
UH, HEAVY CREAM.
JUST REGULAR HEAVY CREAM?
YEP.
NOW WE'RE GOING DOWN
WITH SOME REALLY THIN--
THIS IS--
SOME LARDO? SOME--
IT'S GUANCIALE,
ACTUALLY.
GUANCIALE. HO, HO.
GUANCIALE.
YEAH, GUANCIALE.
GUANCIALE. CHEEKS.
HEY. RIGHT IN HERE, BABY.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I'M TELLING YOU, I CAN'T
BELIEVE THEY DON'T TRY
TO HARVEST ME EVERY WINTER.
SO NOW THAT THE PIZZA
IS JUST SORT OF SET,
THAT'S WHEN WE'RE GONNA CRACK
TWO FARM-FRESH EGGS
RIGHT ON TOP.
THAT'S A NICE PIZZA.
THIS IS REAL FOOD
FOR COLD-WEATHER PEOPLE.
(laughs)
AND THERE YOU GO.
SUNNYSIDE.
IF THAT ISN'T HEAVEN,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IS.
WE DEFINITELY CELEBRATE
DIFFERENT GODS.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
CUT RIGHT THROUGH THE YOLK.
DON'T GO THROUGH THE YOLK!
THIS IS THE BEST PART.
(laughs)
LOOK AT THIS.
THANK YOU.
IT'S LIQUID CHICKEN.
THERE'S 6 1/2-YEAR-OLD KIDS
IN MY FAMILY
WHO EAT THIS PIZZA,
SO YOU MAY WANT TO MAN UP
AND JUST GO FOR IT.
OH! THAT IS HOT!
YOU CAN DO IT.
(sighs)
(mouth full) EVERYBODY KNOWS
IN TRIPLE "D" WORLD
I DON'T LIKE EGGS,
BUT I WILL ACTUALLY
HAVE TO SAY, THIS...
WHOA!
PRETTY DARN GOOD, RIGHT?
THAT'S PRETTY DYNAMITE.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU,
IN THAT COMBINATION
BETWEEN THE GUANCIALE
AND THE LEEKS--
YOU HAVE SOME OF THAT ONION
COMING THROUGH,
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE CREAM--
FANTASTIC CRUST.
AND THE BLACK PEPPER--
THAT'S THE KICKER RIGHT THERE,
IS THE BLACK PEPPER.
THAT MIGHT BE
ONE OF THE ONLY WAYS
I THINK I MIGHT BRANCH OUT
AND HAVE A LITTLE EGG,
BESIDES A CAESAR SALAD.
I'M SO HAPPY RIGHT NOW,
I COULD KISS YOU. (kisses)
(both laugh)
YOU GOTTA BRANCH OUT
OF WHAT YOU THINK YOU KNOW
AND WHAT YOU THINK YOU LIKE.
COMING TO MINNEAPOLIS,
I ALWAYS EXPECT
SOMETHING A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
THIS HAS BEEN OFF THE HOOK.
I WILL BE BACK.
UP NEXT--WE'RE HEADED
TO GEORGETOWN, TEXAS,
WHERE ONE HOMEGROWN STAR...
WE'LL JUST SERVE
THAT HALF TO MATTHEW,
AND THEN THAT HALF TO ME.
IS GETTING HIS FIRST TASTE
OF ANOTHER.
GOT THE KING RANCH CASSEROLE.
DID YOU GROW UP ON IT? NO?
NO. MY MOM
WAS NOT A GOOD COOK.
SORRY, MOM.
YOU KNOW YOU WEREN'T.
(laughter)
♪♪
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY
ON THE EAST COAST
HOW THE BIG SUPER RESTAURANTS
THAT ARE SERVING
BREAKFAST, LUNCH, AND DINNER
MAKE THEIR OWN DESSERTS
IN HOUSE,
SCRATCH-MAKE ALMOST EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU.
WHAT ARE THEY CALLED?
EXACTLY. DINERS.
BUT THE FARTHER YOU GO WEST,
THEY START CALLING THEM
DIFFERENT THINGS,
LIKE COFFEE SHOPS OR...
CAFES.
CA--EXACTLY, MATTHEW.
SO HERE WE ARE
IN GEORGETOWN,
ABOUT 30 MILES NORTH
OF AUSTIN,
TO CHECK OUT
MONUMENT CAFE.
(man) TWO EGGS
OVER EASY, PLEASE.
(man) TWO EGGS OVER EASY.
(man) TEXAS FRIED GULF SHRIMP.
IT'S LIKE WALKING INTO
A '50s DINER,
BUT WITH A REALLY MODERN TWIST.
CHICKEN FRIED STEAK, MASH.
EVERYTHING IS MADE
FROM SCRATCH. MMM.
(woman) HERE YOU ARE.
EVERYTHING'S ORGANIC.
THEY EITHER GROW IT,
OR IT'S LOCALLY GROWN.
GEORGINA, CRUSTED TILAPIA.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT THE FOOD
THAT MAKES IT SO GREAT?
IF IT'S NOT JUST RIGHT,
THEN RUSTY KEEPS WORKING AT IT
TILL IT IS.
THAT'S 'CAUSE OWNER
RUSTY WINKSTERN
IS USED TO WORKING HARD...
TWO MEDIUM SCRAMBLE.
AFTER GROWING UP ON A FARM
IN WESTERN NEW YORK.
I NEED TWO WAFFLES,
A HONEY-GLAZED HAM, PLEASE.
AND HE'S BEEN MIXING
FARM-FRESH FLAVORS
WITH A TASTE OF TEXAS SINCE
OPENING THIS JOINT IN '95.
GOT THE KING RANCH
CASSEROLE.
THERE'S CHICKEN AND THERE'S
CHEESE AND THE PEPPER.
IT'S REALLY A TEXAS THING.
SO IT MAKES TOTAL SENSE
TO DRAG McCONAUGHEY
UP FROM AUSTIN
SO HE CAN GET IN ON THIS.
ISN'T THIS SICK? GOT THIS
FOR HIS 40th BIRTHDAY.
I GOT A LONE STAR LOCAL HERE,
AND I'LL TELL YOU--
THIS DUDE DOES NOT
STRETCH THE TRUTH.
PLUS I FIGURE IF I GET HIM FED,
THERE'S A GOOD SHOT
I GET TO DRIVE THE "Z."
MATTHEW, JUMP IN.
(whistling)
SO LET ME
GET THIS STRAIGHT.
WHERE DOES KING RANCH SAUCE
COME FROM?
TO FEED THE RANCH HANDS
DOWN AT THE KING RANCH,
SOUTH TEXAS,
THEY USED TO MAKE THIS.
OKAY.
START WITH SOME OIL.
GOT OUR ONIONS.
(sizzling)
BELL PEPPER
AND A LITTLE BIT OF CELERY.
COOK THAT DOWN.
OKAY.
GARLIC.
SLICED MUSHROOMS.
THEN WE DEGLAZE IT A LITTLE BIT
WITH SOME WHITE WINE.
A LITTLE SALT.
BLACK PEPPER. CUMINO.
DOWN HERE THE CUMINO
IS CUMIN.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE CALLING CUMIN?
YEAH. CUMINO.
YEAH.
CUMINO.
A LITTLE CHILI POWDER.
A LITTLE RO-TEL TOMATOES
AND GREEN CHILES.
(Matthew laughs)
SO WE'VE GOT CANNED TOMATOES
WITH SOME--
LIKE A HATCH GREEN CHILE.
SMELLS LIKE MEXICAN FOOD.
FLOUR IN.
IF YOU HAVE FAT,
THAT'S WHEN IT STARTS TO WORK
TOGETHER AND BUILD THE ROOT.
WHERE'D THE FAT COME FROM?
THE FAT CAME FROM--
ONE, WE STARTED WITH OIL.
RIGHT.
NOW HE'LL SLOWLY ADD IN
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
CHICKEN STOCK.
AND FINISH OFF WITH SOME
WHOLE MILK.
ALL RIGHT, SO YOU JUST
SIT THERE AND LET THIS
REDUCE A LITTLE BIT.
HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA REDUCE THAT?
MAYBE FIVE, SIX MINUTES.
AND THEN IT'S GONNA SETTLE
AND...
YEP, TIGHTEN RIGHT UP.
GET A LITTLE VISCOUS?
YEP.
AND THEN WE'LL GET TO EAT.
THAT'S THE BEST PART.
AND RACE THE CARS.
THAT'LL BE LATER.
(laughs)
BLOW THEM DOORS COMPLETELY OFF,
MELBA TOAST.
(laughter)
SO WE'RE NOW WE'RE ABOUT
READY TO ASSEMBLE THE CASSEROLE
AND PUT IT IN THE OVEN.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THE WORD
"CASSEROLE" EXACTLY WORKS.
"ENCHILADA STACK,"
OR SOMETHING?
"CASHILADA." MMM...
CAS-- (laughs)
LOOKS LIKE A BIT
OF AN ENCHILADA.
I KNOW.
I LIKE "CASHILADA."
I THINK CHANGE IT.
CASHILADA? OKAY.
I'LL GO AND GET THE SHARPIE
AND CHANGE ALL THE MENUS
BY THIS AFTERNOON.
OKAY, SO HIT IT.
LADLE THE SAUCE DOWN.
SO THE TORTILLAS
DON'T STICK AND DON'T DRY OUT.
EXACTLY.
AND WHOSE RECIPE WAS THIS?
UH, EVERYONE IN TEXAS
HAS A DIFFERENT RECIPE.
LOCAL--
THIS IS A STAPLE?
YEP. DID YOU GROW UP ON IT? NO?
NO. MY MOM WAS NOT
A GOOD COOK.
SORRY, MOM.
YOU KNOW YOU WEREN'T.
(laughter)
PULLED CHICKEN.
DARK AND WHITE.
YEP. GRATED MONTEREY JACK
AND CHEDDAR CHEESE.
MORE SAUCE.
THANKS FOR USING
DARK MEAT.
MORE FLAVORFUL?
OH, YEAH.
IT'S GOT THE MOST FLAVOR.
IT'S GOT THE MOST FAT.
OKAY, SO THREE LAYERS OF IT.
THIS IS THE LAST ONE.
YEP.
IS THERE GONNA BE ANY CHEESE
ON THE TOP OF IT?
YEP.
WE'LL JUST SERVE
THAT HALF TO MATTHEW,
AND THEN THAT HALF TO ME.
SOUNDS GOOD.
INTO THE OVEN THEN.
ALL RIGHT.
AND THEN HOW LONG
WILL IT BAKE OFF?
UH, ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
350-DEGREE OVEN.
NOT COVERED?
NOT COVERED.
HERE'S OUR KING RANCH
CASSEROLE.
SERVING IT WITH PINTO BEANS
AND ROASTED ROOT VEGETABLES.
I LIKE THE CORNER.
(laughing) YOU JUST JUMPED
RIGHT IN AND TOOK THE CORNER?
YOU GOT THREE MORE.
YEAH, THERE'S THREE--
(laughter)
SO THOSE GREEN CHILES--
THEY COME THROUGH.
(mouth full) CREAMY.
NOT SPICY.
WHICH GETS MISINTERPRETED
A LOT OF TIMES
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
TEX-MEX FOOD.
MM-HMM.
JUST LIKE MATTHEW WAS SAYING,
HAVING THAT DARK MEAT--
(mouth full) I THINK
YOU DID THE RIGHT BALANCE.
YEAH, REAL GOOD
CONSISTENCY, MAN.
NOT TOO WET, NOT TOO DRY.
SHOVEL DOWN
A PLATE FULL OF THAT?
EASILY.
LOOK AT HIS SMILE.
CASHILADA.
THAT'S LIKE
TEXAS COMFORT FOOD.
DUDE, NICE JOB.
THANK YOU MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
MATTHEW, MY BROTHER.
YOU'RE THE MAN.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
YOU, TOO.
SEE? I TOLD YOU
I WOULDN'T LET YOU DOWN.
COME OUT SOUTH-EAST
END OF TEXAS MORE OFTEN, MAN.
YOU JUST SHOW ME THE JOINTS,
I'LL BE HERE.
UP NEXT...
THIS IS PIG 'N' WAFFLE?
PIG 'N' WAFFLE.
WE'RE HANGIN'
AT THE MONUMENT...
THIS IS A CULINARY
INSTITUTION.
AND HAMMIN' IT UP...
GINGER.
MARY ANN. PROFESSOR.
WITH A NEW KIND
OF BREAKFAST SANDWICH.
FOLD IT OVER AND MAKE
A SANDWICH. THAT'S WHAT I DO.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS THINKIN'!
MMM. EXCELLENT.
♪♪
WE'RE PARKED
OUTSIDE THE MONUMENT CAFE
IN GEORGETOWN, TEXAS,
WHERE RUSTY WINKSTERN...
NEED A SWEET POTATO FRY DOWN,
VEGGIE FRY DOWN.
HAS BUILT A GINORMOUS CAMPUS
OF COOKIN' AND EATIN'.
KING RANCH CASSEROLE
FOR YOU, ALSO.
THIS IS
A CULINARY INSTITUTION.
I JUST LOVE STAINLESS.
HOW MANY SQUARE FEET?
6,600.
AND THEN WE HAVE
AN ORGANIC GARDEN HERE.
WE HAVE AN ORGANIC MARKET.
EVERYTHING RAISED LOCAL.
FARM-TO-TABLE FRESHNESS.
YOU KNOW WHAT? IT SAID
"MONUMENT" OUT FRONT.
IT'S SHOULD SAY LIKE
THE "U.S.S. ENTERPRISE."
(laughs)
OKAY, READY FOR BREAKFAST?
BUTTERMILK PANCAKES
WITH PEPPERED BACON.
CRISPY WAFFLE WITH HAM
FOR YOU, SIR.
CRISPY WAFFLE,
HONEY-GLAZED HAM.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
OKAY, SO WHAT IS THE HAM
GONNA BE FOR?
IT GOES ON OUR WAFFLE.
THIS IS PIG 'N' WAFFLE?
PIG 'N' WAFFLE.
FIRST THING WE'RE GOING TO DO
IS MAKE A MARINADE.
START WITH SOME BROWN SUGAR.
LOCALLY PRODUCED
ORGANIC HONEY, OF COURSE.
FRESH-SQUEEZED
ORANGE JUICE.
AND THEN WE MARINATE
THE HAM.
THEN WE'LL PUT IT IN THE WALK-IN
FOR 24 HOURS.
OKAY, WE TAKE THIS,
LET IT MARINATE,
THEN WE'RE GONNA COOK IT OFF
AND MAKE SOME WAFFLES.
YES, SIR.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT. EGG YOLKS.
MILK.
FLOUR.
SALT. VANILLA.
BAKING POWDER. SUGAR.
AND THEN WE'LL STIR THIS UP.
DO OUR EGG WHITES.
(whirring)
THERE WE GO.
OKAY.
AND WE'LL FOLD IN
SOME EGG WHITES.
FOR THAT EXTRA FLUFF.
GONNA ADD SOME MELTED
SHORTENING RIGHT AT THE END.
KEEPS IT FROM STICKING.
SO WE HAVE
OUR OVEN-ROASTED HAM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A GLAZE
TO GO ON TOP OF IT.
WE'LL START WITH SOME SUGAR.
GINGER.
MARY ANN.
(laughs) PAPRIKA.
PROFESSOR.
NUTMEG.
CLOVE, CINNAMON,
AND DRY MUSTARD.
OKAY.
THEN WE'LL JUST
STIR THIS UP.
MORE OF OUR LOCAL HONEY.
SO COVER THIS ALL UP.
NOW OUR SUGAR GLAZE.
(clicks on, whooshing)
NOW WE'RE GONNA
TORCH IT, JUST CARAMELIZE.
THIS IS CRÈME BRU-PIG?
(laughs) CRÈME BRU-PIG.
NOW WE'LL MAKE
OUR CRISPY WAFFLE.
WHILE WE'RE WAITING
FOR THE WAFFLE,
SLICE THE HAM AND TRY IT?
I BELIEVE THAT'D BE
A GOOD IDEA.
I THINK THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
(laughs)
NICE CRUST ON THAT.
(mouth full) GOT REAL
TEXTURE TO IT.
A SCOOP OF BUTTER ON THAT.
WAIT A SECOND.
(laughing) SO IS THIS
HOW YOU DO IT?
WELL, YOU FOLD IT OVER
AND MAKE SANDWICH.
THAT'S WHAT I'D DO.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS
THINKIN'!
NOW YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEET THERE
OF THE PURE MAPLE SYRUP.
(mouth full)
WAFFLE'S NICE AND LIGHT.
GOOD LITTLE CRISP.
JUST THESE AIR POCKETS.
IT'S LIKE AN ENGLISH MUFFIN
OF WAFFLES.
YOU GET THE SWEETNESS
OF THE WAFFLE,
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT MAPLE SYRUP
TO KIND OF COUNTERBALANCE
THE...
(mouth full)
SALTINESS OF THE HAM.
MMM. EXCELLENT. NICE JOB.
GOOD. THANK YOU.
GREAT WAFFLE.
CRISPY WAFFLE WITH HAM
FOR YOU, MA'AM.
(man) IT'S PERFECT EVERY TIME.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE
BREAKFAST ITEMS HERE.
THAT'S MY KIND OF BREAKFAST
RIGHT THERE, BUDDY.
GOOD.
IS THIS A SOUTHERN STAPLE?
IT IS.
IT IS NOW.
IT IS NOW, YEAH.
(laughs) THERE YOU GO.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION
"OF DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO FIND
THE RECIPES
FROM SOME OF THE JOINTS
WE VISIT,
WELL, GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
(man) WHAT IS THAT?
(Ann) ALL RIGHT.
OHH!
(laughing)
YOU GOT--THAT'S KINDA--
(laughter)