HEY THERE, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' IT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I FEEL LIKE WINNIE THE POOH!
WE'RE ROCKIN' OUT...
(imitates caw)
WITH SOME REAL-DEAL CLASSICS.
NOW WE CAN COMMENCE.
IN MINNEAPOLIS, MINNESOTA...
(whirring)
SHH! DON'T TALK.
JUST LISTEN.
THE FAMILY-FIRST
ITALIAN JOINT...
TAKE US TO THE PROMISED LAND.
CRANKIN' OUT FRESH PASTA...
HOW DO YOU SLEEP IN BED
WITH IT?
AND DISHIN' UP RIGHTEOUS PIE.
I'M MOVING TO MINNEAPOLIS.
AND IN ARLINGTON, TEXAS...
HERE WE GO.
A STRAIGHT-UP BURGER JOINT...
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
MIXING IN BARBECUE...
THIS IS ECLECTIC.
WITH A TEXAS LEGEND.
(crowd cheers)
EARL CAMPBELL IS GONNA
SHOW UP.
THE CHEF MAY KNOW
WHAT HE'S DOING.
IT'S GONNA BE ONE OF THOSE
KINDA DAYS.
(rings clatter)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE COOLEST
CATS I KNOW IN THIS WORLD
IS OUR DIRECTOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY
FOR "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES,"
A GUY NAMED ANTHONY RODRIGUEZ.
NOW WE CALL HIM CHICO.
HE'S THE ONE
THAT'S SHOOTING IT RIGHT NOW.
WELL, CHICO SAYS TO ME,
"LISTEN.
"I LIVE IN MINNEAPOLIS
WITH MY WIFE,
"MY TWO BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTERS,
AND I'VE GOT AN ITALIAN JOINT
THAT WILL ROCK YOUR WORLD."
THIS DUDE'S SEEN IT ALL,
SO I GOTTA CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS BRODERS'
CUCINA ITALIANA.
ANTHONY, YOU AND I HAVE SHOT
OVER 250,
300 LOCATIONS TOGETHER.
YEAH.
YOU SAY THIS IS
IN THE--
NO QUESTION.
AT LEAST IN THE TOP TEN?
THIS IS ONE OF THE FIRST
I'VE HAD,
ON THE SHOW OR ANYWHERE,
THAT'S AS CLOSE TO THE STUFF
I GREW UP WITH IN BROOKLYN.
CHICKEN PARM WITH SPAGHETTI.
ITALIAN FOOD IS LIKE THIS
IN MINNEAPOLIS?
THIS IS THE ITALIAN FOOD
IN MINNEAPOLIS.
THIS IS THE STAPLE?
OH, YEAH.
GO BACK TO ITALY,
THIS IS WHAT YOU GET.
IT'S ALL ABOUT LOVE
AND FOOD AND FAMILY.
HI.
KEY INGREDIENTS
FROM MOLLY BRODER
AND HER LATE HUSBAND TOM
WHEN THEY OPENED THE JOINT
BACK IN '82.
WHERE'S THE PASSION
COME FROM?
IT COMES FROM GROWING UP
EATING FAMILY MEALS--
FAMILY DINNER EVERY NIGHT.
IT COMES FROM
LIVING IT.
LITERALLY.
TODAY THE THREE BRODER SONS
ARE PITCHING IN--
CHARLIE ON WINE,
AND DANNY IN THE KITCHEN
WITH HEAD CHEF THOMAS.
YOU GUYS MAKE
EVERYTHING FRESH?
EVERYTHING.
I'M MOVING TO MINNEAPOLIS.
ESPECIALLY WHEN I FIND OUT
THEY'RE TRAVELING TO ITALY
TO SHOP FOR THE SHELVES,
AND CRANKIN' OUT FRESH PASTA
DAILY WITH THIS BAD BOY.
(motors whirring)
THIS, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS A HOT ROD I DON'T OWN YET.
THIS IS A SHEETER.
YEAH, THIS'LL DO
THE MIXING OF THE DOUGH.
THIS'LL MAKE OUR EGG PASTA.
300, 400 PORTIONS A DAY.
HOW DO YOU SLEEP IN BED
WITH IT?
JUST LIKE THIS.
LIKE THIS?
YEAH.
THERE SHOULD BE
FLOWERS OVER HERE.
LIKE A LITTLE SHRINE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE TO BRING
SOMETHING, LIKE AN OFFERING.
(resounds)
NOW WE CAN COMMENCE.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
DURUM FLOUR.
TENDER, BUT WITH A GOOD CHEW.
YEAH.
AND THIS RIGHT HERE
IS SO I CAN'T FALL IN
LIKE "WILLY WONKA."
"AUGUSTUS!"
THE LAST BIT IN THERE.
(chuckling) FIRE IT UP!
(whirring)
SHH!
DON'T TALK. JUST LISTEN.
(whirring continues)
MMM.
ALL RIGHT. SO WE'LL GET
THE FLOUR MOVING
WITH WHOLE EGGS--
NICE AND SLOW.
LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THAT UP
FOR ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
GET A ROLLER SET IN THERE.
WE'RE GONNA OPEN THE DOOR HERE,
AND IT'S GONNA COME OUT.
AND IT'S HARD ENOUGH
AND DENSE ENOUGH
THAT IT'LL PUSH ITSELF
ONTO THE ROLL?
YEP. IT'LL FILL IT RIGHT UP.
NO!
THIS IS THE ROLL AFTER IT'S
COME OUT OF THE LAMINATOR.
AND WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT
AGAIN?
WE'RE GONNA ROLL IT AGAIN.
WHOA! IT'S JUST CUTTING IT
IN USABLE LENGTHS.
IT'S CUTTING TO--
TO THE WIDTH, YEP.
THE WIDTH AND THE LENGTH.
SO WE'LL DO A LITTLE
SEMOLINA,
AND THAT'LL KEEP IT
NICE AND LOOSE.
AND THEN YOU CAN JUST
LAY THIS OUT ON SHEET TRAYS,
AND YOU'RE READY TO GO
TO PORTION...
READY TO PORTION IT UP,
READY FOR IT TO GO ON THE LINE.
NOW DO YOU EVER DRY
ANY OF YOUR PASTAS?
WE DON'T, NO.
IT'S ALL FRESH.
EVERYTHING'S FRESH
ALL THE TIME.
EVERYTHING WE DO HERE
IS FRESH.
WE MAKE IT DAILY.
CONSISTENCY. EVERY TIME.
NOW I JUST GOTTA FIGURE OUT
HOW TO STASH IT IN THE CAMARO.
CHANCES ARE, THOUGH,
THEY'D MISS
THE THOUSAND POUNDS OF PASTA
A WEEK THIS BABY CRANKS OUT.
IT'S THE BASE
FOR THE LASAGNA,
THE CHICKEN PARM,
AND THE TOP SELLER,
A HOUSE-MADE BOLOGNESE.
OKAY, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE MAKING BOLOGNESE.
TAKE US
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
START WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL, BUTTER,
ONIONS, CARROTS,
AND CELERY.
WE'RE GONNA SWEAT THAT DOWN?
YEP.
AND THEN WHAT MEATS ARE WE
MAKING THIS BOLOGNESE WITH?
WE'RE DOING PORK,
PASTURED GROUND BEEF.
LOVE IT.
SO OUR MEAT
IS NICE AND BROWN.
READY FOR WHITE WINE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA LET THAT COOK
DOWN FOR A COUPLE MINUTES HERE.
THEN WE GO WITH THE MILK.
JUST WHOLE MILK?
YEP. AND THIS IS WHAT REALLY
MAKES THE SAUCE,
IS THE NUTMEG.
MILK'S ALL ABSORBED.
WE'RE READY FOR TOMATOES.
SALT. PEPPER. THAT'S IT.
TWO HOURS, AND, UH,
IT'LL BE READY.
GO AHEAD AND, UH,
DROP OUR PASTA.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF BUTTER IN THE PAN.
(sizzling)
OKAY, PASTA'S READY.
FRESH NESTED FETTUCCINE.
YEAH.
DO ANOTHER LITTLE HIT
OVER THE FLAME.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
GRANA PADANO.
AND A LITTLE FRESH NUTMEG.
(scrapes)
(mouth full) I'VE ENJOYED
PASTA ALL OVER THE WORLD.
I PRIDE MYSELF ON MAKING
MY OWN PASTA.
AND THIS IS FANTASTIC.
THIS IS LIKE THE ROCKET
THAT'S GONNA GO
TO MARS, MAN.
IT IS TENDER, IT'S FLAVORFUL.
BALANCE IS THE KEY.
THIS IS WHERE IT COULD
ALMOST TURN INTO
NO MORE LAUGHING,
NO MORE FUN,
THE PASTA COMA HAS BEGUN.
(laughs)
ONE FET BOLO.
AND THE BOLOGNESE.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
NOW IS IT
A LITTLE BIT GOOD,
EXTRA SUPER GOOD,
OR REALLY FANTASTIC
AMAZING GOOD?
SUPER-DUPER-DUPER-DUPER-DUPER
GOOD!
(gasps)
DELICIOUS.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT?
FROM THE EXPERIENCE
THAT I'VE HAD,
AND HOW YOU TREAT FOOD,
AND HOW YOU GO TO ITALY
TO SHOP IT,
AND SHARE RESPONSIBILITY--
THERE'S NOT A LOT OF THESE.
'CAUSE FRESH PASTA'S
JUST THE TIP OF THE ICEBERG.
THIS JOINT'S LOADED
WITH IMPORTED SPECIALTY FOODS,
A FULL DELI,
AND A MIDWEST DEDICATION
TO BAKING UP
AN EAST COAST-STYLE PIE.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
THAT'S A REAL-DEAL PIE.
YOU CAN'T LEAVE BRODERS'
WITHOUT PICKING UP A SLICE.
BETTER THAN ANY PIZZA
IN NEW YORK. SORRY, BROOKLYN.
(laughs)
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
♪♪
SO ANYHOW,
I'M LIVING IN FRANCE,
AND I SAY TO MYSELF,
"FRAN--"
OH, WELCOME BACK.
TRIPLE "D,"
HANGING OUT AT BRODER''
IN MINNEAPOLIS.
WOW!
HAD TO HAVE A LITTLE NAP,
A LITTLE ESPRESSO.
BUT WE'RE BACK, AND NOW
WE'RE GONNA MAKE...
PROSCIUTTO
AND ARUGULA PIZZA.
PIZZA? THREATEN ME
WITH A GOOD TIME.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S START
STRETCHING SOME DOUGH.
NOW THIS PIZZA DOUGH,
YOU GUYS MAKE YOURSELF.
YEAH. EVERY DAY.
AND THIS WILL MAKE
WHAT SIZE PIE?
18 INCH.
BIG NEW YORK-STYLE?
BIG ONE, YEAH.
AND THE REASON YOU GO
AFTER THAT KINDA PIE?
MY DAD GREW
UP IN NEW YORK,
AND WE FELL IN LOVE
WITH THE PIZZA.
AND THERE'S NOTHING LIKE--
YOU KNOW,
YOU TALK ABOUT THAT
BIG NEW YORK SLICE.
AND IF IT'S GREASY ENOUGH,
YOU EAT THE PLATE WITH IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
OKAY.
YOU'RE GONNA THROW
THIS THING?
IF I HAD A TALLER KITCHEN.
OR IF YOU WERE SHORTER.
(laughs)
THAT'S ABOUT AS MUCH
AS I CAN DO IN THIS SPACE.
NICE GLUTEN ON THAT DOUGH.
MY BLING WOULD HAVE
BEEN THROUGH IT BY NOW.
START WITH GARLIC OIL.
JUST CRUSHED GARLIC,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
HAVE A NICE PERFUME.
SOME SHREDDED MOZZ.
JUST LAYING DOWN THE BASE?
YEAH.
THEN WE'LL DO A LITTLE BIT
OF FRESH MOZZARELLA.
ALL RIGHT.
WE SHOULD PROBABLY
JUST CHECK THIS.
IS THIS, UH...
TUNA FISH?
THIS IS--
(mouth full)
THAT'S NOT TUNA FISH!
(laughs)
(chuckles, mouth full)
I THOUGHT IT WAS TUNA FISH.
NO, THAT'S PROSCIUTTO.
(chuckles)
MMM.
THIS IS GREAT STUFF.
THIS IS SOME OF THE BEST
DOMESTIC PROSCIUTTO
YOU CAN GET.
NICE AND SWEET.
FOR US, IT'S A LOCAL PRODUCT.
WE LOVE IT.
NICE, GENEROUS PORTION
ON HERE.
READY FOR THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP?
WE'RE GOING 550.
550, SPIN IT ONCE, AND--WHAT?
7, 8 MINUTES?
EXACTLY.
OHH!
GRAB THAT PIE.
LOOK AT IT.
IT'S AT 18 INCHES,
AND STILL SO THIN
AND SO CRISP, IT LITERALLY
STANDS ON ITS OWN.
THAT'S A REAL-DEAL PIE.
LET'S FINISH IT OFF.
ARUGULA.
A LITTLE BIT OF ROMANO.
(slicing)
WE WANT TO LOOK...
LIKE THAT.
OOH! IT'S LIKE CULINARY
DISNEYLAND FOR ME.
(laughs)
(crunches)
(mouth full) MMM! NOW DON'T
BE OFFENDED WHEN I DO THIS.
NOT ALL THE CRUST
HAS TO BE AT ONE END!
(laughs)
I LIKE THE CRUST
TO BE EVERYWHERE.
I LIKE THAT SUPER CRUST.
THIN, CHEWY, CRUNCHY...
THAT OLIVE OIL--
NICE, 'CAUSE IT DOESN'T MAKE
THE CHEESE DO ALL THE WORK.
THAT'S ALL THE INGREDIENTS
I WANT.
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
YOU HAVE TO SELL THE TICKETS
TO THE CARIBBEAN.
COME SEE THIS GUY.
IT'S CERTAINLY THE BEST PIZZA
IN TOWN.
BETTER THAN ANY PIZZA
IN NEW YORK.
SORRY, BROOKLYN. (laughs)
VERY BOLD FLAVORS.
JUST MADE WITH LOVE.
IT'S LIKE A PARTY
IN YOUR MOUTH, TOO--
ALL THE FLAVORS--
THESE ARE ALL MY LINES.
THERE ARE ALL MY LINES.
THEY'RE ALL YOUR LINES?
NO, YOU CAN'T--
YOU CAN'T USE THAT.
YOU GOTTA HAVE
YOUR OWN LINES.
(laughs)
BUT IT'S THE REAL DEAL?
IT'S REAL.
WHEN ANTHONY TOLD ME
ABOUT THIS,
AND HE SAID,
"I'M REALLY TELLING YOU,
YOU'RE GONNA FLIP OUT,"
I DIDN'T THINK HE DEFINED
"FLIP OUT" ENOUGH.
(laughter)
THERE'S A NEW DEFINITION.
AH, THAT'S SWEET.
UP NEXT...
EVERYTHING'S
GOT A KICKER.
WE'RE HEADED
TO ARLINGTON, TEXAS...
TIME-OUT.
FOR A BURGER JOINT...
THAT'S A DIFFERENT
CATEGORY OF BURGER.
GRILLING UP THE UNEXPECTED.
YOU HAVE SO MANY THINGS
GOING ON IN THIS BURGER
THAT ARE OUTSTANDING.
♪♪
(door closes)
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
I HAVE A REPUTATION--
I KNOW. A REPUTATION OF KNOWING
SOMETHING ABOUT BURGERS.
I MEAN, I HAVE MY PLACE--
GUY'S BURGER JOINT--
AND I'VE PROBABLY SEEN
OVER 3,000 OR 4,000 DOZEN
BURGER JOINTS ON TRIPLE "D."
SO WHEN I CRUISE
INTO ARLINGTON, TEXAS,
AND I HEAR THAT THERE'S A DUDE
THAT IS TAKING BRISKET,
COOKING THE BRISKET,
AND MIXING IT
WITH THE GROUND BEEF
TO MAKE A BURGER...
I GOTTA CHECK THIS OUT.
THIS IS CHOP HOUSE BURGERS.
BUNS GOING IN.
IT'S AMAZING. I LIVE FOR IT.
PICKING UP CHOP HOUSE BURGER.
BEST BURGERS IN TEXAS.
10 PEPPER BURGER,
SIDE OF RINGS.
SO THIS IS A REAL-DEAL
BURGER JOINT?
IT IS.
AND BEHIND EVERY
CHOP HOUSE BURGER
IS CHEF KENNY MILLS.
(man) KENNY SPENDS
A LOT OF TIME
AND A LOT OF ENERGY
MAKING SURE
THAT HE MAKES A PERFECT BURGER
FOR EVERY CUSTOMER
THAT COMES IN.
SOMETHING HE PICKED UP
FROM 25 YEARS IN FINE DINING.
ORDER UP.
HE HAS SOME VERY UNIQUE
COMBINATIONS OF INGREDIENTS.
BUT THERE'S ONE THAT'S GOT ME
ALL RILED UP.
WE TAKE BRISKET--
SLOW-ROASTED BRISKET,
CHOP IT UP, MIX IT IN
WITH THE HAMBURGER MEAT.
TIME-OUT. (lowered voice)
I THINK HE SAID
HE TAKES COOKED BRISKET
AND MIXES IT
WITH RAW BURGER MEAT.
(speaks indistinctly)
LET'S FIND OUT.
(laughs) SOUNDED LIKE
FOR A SECOND
YOU SAID YOU WERE TAKING
COOKED BRISKET
AND MIXING IT UP WITH
RAW HAMBURGER MEAT,
MAKING A BURGER OUT OF THAT.
YEAH. RIGHT.
THIS IS GONNA BE
INTERESTING.
IT'S GOOD.
LET'S DO IT.
WE'RE GONNA START OUT
MAKING THE HOUSE-MADE
STEAK SAUCE.
THERE RAISINS IN THIS?
YEAH, RAISINS.
NICE LITTLE FRUIT TO IT.
IT'S GONNA BE ONE OF THOSE
KINDA DAYS.
WE'RE GONNA CARAMELIZE
THE ONIONS
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF ORANGE JUICE.
YOU THROW A CANARY IN THERE?
(laughs) YEAH.
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT
SOME MOLASSES IN THERE.
SMELL THAT MOLASSES
RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
(sizzling)
RED WINE VINEGAR.
BALSAMIC VINEGAR.
SOY SAUCE.
THIS IS A HEARTY SAUCE,
BROTHER.
WE GOT THE RAISINS.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
I LIKE ALL THE CHARACTERS
YOU PUT IN THE POOL.
REGULAR OLD CHILI SAUCE?
YEAH. HORSERADISH IN IT.
THIS IS ECLECTIC.
AND THEN WE HAVE SOME
BLACK PEPPERCORN.
AND THIS IS CHICKEN BASE.
AND THEN SOME BEEF BASE.
THIS IS GONNA BE... RICH.
COUPLE GALLONS OF WATER.
NOW WE BRING THIS TO A BOIL,
AND WE TAKE IT DOWN TO A SIMMER
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
SO WE'RE COOLED DOWN?
NICE AND COOL.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND UP
A GOOD BATCH OF IT HERE.
(whirring)
GOTTA BREAK DOWN
THOSE PEPPERCORNS.
AH, IT DID TIGHTEN UP.
(smacks lips) MMM!
AH, THAT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT HOW PROUD HE IS.
I DIDN'T SEE ALL YOUR FEATHERS
COME OUT, PEACOCK. (laughs)
YOU KNOW...
(imitates cawing)
TEN--TEN YEARS
IN THE MAKING.
NICELY DONE.
WE GOT A BRISKET. WE'RE
GONNA PUT IT IN A PAN HERE.
MIREPOIX, CARROTS, ONIONS.
I ADD A COUPLE JALAPEÑOS
TO MINE,
JUST 'CAUSE WE'RE IN TEXAS.
'CAUSE YOU LIVE
ON THE EDGE.
PEPPERCORN, SOME BAY LEAVES.
THROW A LITTLE
WATER IN IT,
WRAP IT WITH SOME FOIL.
PUT IT IN THE OVEN
FOR ABOUT SIX HOURS
AT 400 DEGREES.
(foil rustling)
YO, WE'RE JUST TALKING ABOUT
PULL-APART TENDER.
NOW CHOP IT UP. SO YOU'RE
GONNA GET SOME CHUNKS.
YOU'RE GONNA GET SOME CHUNKS.
WE'RE GONNA USE
A GOOD HANDFUL.
GET IT ALL MIXED IN THERE
REAL GOOD.
SO THAT'S OUR HOUSE SEASONING
FOR THE BURGER.
WE'LL ADD SOME
GRANULATED GARLIC
AND SOME GRANULATED ONION
IN IT, AND RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
WHAT ARE WE BURNING?
MESQUITE WOOD.
GIVES IT THAT
GREAT FLAVOR, AND REALLY--
AND BURNS HOT.
BURNS REALLY HOT.
THIS IS GONNA BE GOOD.
BURGER'S ABOUT MEDIUM
RIGHT NOW.
AHH! THAT STEAK SAUCE
IS RIDICULOUS.
I LIKE ALL THE LITTLE
PARTICULATES IN THERE.
TOP IT WITH A COUPLE
OF PIECES OF SLICED BACON.
SMOKED CHEDDAR CHEESE.
SLIDE THIS RIGHT IN THE OVEN
FOR A COUPLE MINUTES,
LET IT GET NICE AND MELTED.
SHREDDED LETTUCE.
ROMA TOMATOES.
PICKLE CHIPS AND SLICED ONIONS,
REAL THIN,
SO THAT WHEN YOU PUT THE BURGER
ON, IT ALMOST COOKS THE ONIONS--
THAT'S THE WAY
TO DO IT, MAN.
AND THAT IS
OUR CHOP HOUSE BURGER.
(exhales)
MMM!
(mouth full) YOU HAVE SO MANY
THINGS GOING ON IN THIS BURGER
THAT ARE OUTSTANDING.
CHEW FROM THAT--
FROM THAT BRISKET.
MMM!
YOU GOT THIS CONTRAST
TAKING PLACE,
AND WE LOVE CONTRAST.
THEN YOU BACK IT UP
WITH THE MESQUITE.
ANYTIME YOU CAN PUT SMOKE
ON SOMETHING LIKE THIS--
LOOK AT THAT.
FANTASTIC.
BUT THE KICKER--
'CAUSE EVERYTHING'S
GOT A KICKER--
IS THAT.
THAT SENDS IT OVER THE TOP.
MMM!
(mouth full) THAT'S A DIFFERENT
CATEGORY OF BURGER.
YOU ROCKED THAT, DUDE.
GET READY. TROUBLE'S
COMING TO YOUR DOOR.
(laughs)
I HAVE A CHOP HOUSE BURGER.
THE MEAT TOGETHER--
THE MIXTURE--IS WONDERFUL.
LISTEN, THAT STEAK SAUCE
HE PUTS ON THERE--
MMM!
IT'S AWESOME, ISN'T IT?
FORGET ABOUT IT.
BURGERS COMING UP.
THE THING THAT MAKES THIS PLACE
WHAT IT IS
IS THE DEDICATION THAT
KENNY PUTS IN THE KITCHEN.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN TO COOK,
KENNY?
I'VE BEEN COOKING SINCE I WAS
ABOUT 15.
I WAS DOING STEAKHOUSES
IN DALLAS.
I TURNED 50 AND I THOUGHT,
"WELL, IT'S TIME
FOR A MIDLIFE CRISIS."
I COULDN'T GET
THE RED CONVERTIBLE,
SO I GOT THE RESTAURANT.
AND DECIDED TO STICK
WITH THE BASICS.
BURGER GOING DOWN.
AND BEFORE YOU FINISH
YOUR FIRST BURGER,
YOU'LL BE PLANNING
YOUR SECOND BURGER.
AND THERE'S PLENTY
TO CHOOSE FROM.
TEN BURGERS ON THE MENU?
RIGHT.
BUT EACH ONE'S GOT A FUNKY
UNIQUENESS.
YES.
THE TEXICAN BURGER--
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
MIXED WITH PICO DE GALLO...
(crunches)
OR THE CAROLINA,
A COMBO OF PULLED PORK,
BARBECUE SAUCE, AND SLAW.
I'VE HAD SEVERAL
OF HIS BURGERS.
I GOT THE 10 PEPPER BURGER
TODAY.
THE 10 PEPPER BURGER?
YEAH.
OKAY, SO WE'VE GOT
RED BELLS, POBLANOS,
GREEN BELLS, ANCHOS,
CHILI DE ARBOL...
(speaks indistinctly)
CALIFORNIAS?
NEW MEXICO.
AND ADD SOME DICED-UP
HABANERO
AND SOME DICED-UP
JALAPEÑO.
AND FOR THE TENTH?
TABASCO AIOLI.
GOES ON THE BURGER?
GOES ON THE TOP OF THE BUN.
TEN PEPPERS
ALL INTO ONE BURGER.
WE'RE GONNA GRILL THESE.
ADDS SOME NICE--NICE SMOKINESS
TO IT, TOO.
OVER THE MESQUITE--
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
AND WHILE THOSE ARE CHARRING,
WE'RE GONNA REHYDRATE THESE.
GOT OUR WATER BOILING.
LOVE ANCHO.
OH, YEAH.
SO YOU JUST PULL THIS.
OKAY.
JUST TAKING THE STEM
OFF THE TOP OF IT.
GOOD MINCE ON EVERYTHING.
BEFORE THEY HAD
FOOD PROCESSORS,
YOUR BUDDY JUST STOOD HERE
AND JUST KEPT DROPPING THEM
INTO YOUR CHOPPING ZONE.
GOT THE DICED HABANEROS,
AND YOU GOT
THE DICED JALAPEÑOS.
LET'S GET THIS GOING, MAN.
I AIN'T GOT--
(stops chopping)
(resumes chopping)
ALL RIGHT.
COMING AT YOU.
GOTTA EARN YOUR KEEP
AROUND HERE.
NOW YOU START WORKING IT IN.
IT'S GONNA BE ONE
FORTIFIED BURGER.
NICE SEASONING ON THE TOP.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION,
SALT AND PEPPER--
THERE WE GO.
(clattering)
(sizzling)
CHIEFTAIN CHILI BURGER.
PEPPER JACK CHEESE.
SHREDDED LETTUCE
WITH OUR TOMATOES,
PICKLES, ONIONS.
SUPER THIN ONIONS.
THE TENTH CHILI--
TABASCO MAYO.
OKAY.
HERE WE GO.
10 PEPPER BURGER.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW YOU SAY THIS IS
NOT SPICY?
IT'S NOT LIKE
OFF-THE-CHAIN SPICY.
THAT'S COMING FROM A DUDE
IN TEXAS
FROM A DUDE FROM CALIFORNIA.
(mouth full) GOT A LOT
OF FLAVOR. GOOD MEAT.
AGAIN, THE PERFECT BALANCE
OF ALL YOUR KEY ITEMS.
(crunches)
(mouth full) AND THEN
THAT MÉLANGE OF PEPPERS.
GREAT FLAVOR WITHOUT BEING
STUPID HOT.
ANOTHER SMASHING SUCCESS,
MAN.
DOING GOOD, MAN!
THANK YOU.
10 PEPPER BURGER.
THE BEST SPICY BURGER I'VE HAD.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
10 PEPPER BURGER.
(woman) HAS A GOOD KICK TO IT.
ORDER UP.
I LOVE THE FOOD THAT HE COOKS.
I SEE THAT YOU HAVE ON YOUR
MENU SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL.
GUMBO. IT'S MADE WITH
EARL CAMPBELL SAUSAGE.
EARL'S KIND OF A LOCAL HERO
HERE IN TEXAS.
"KIND OF"? NUMBER 34,
ONE OF MY ALL-TIME HEROES.
AND ON TOP OF IT ALL,
EARL CAMPBELL IS GONNA SHOW UP--
WHEN WE COME BACK.
HANGING OUT AT THE CHOP HOUSE,
IN ARLINGTON, IN TEXAS,
ON TRIPLE "D."
EARL CAMPBELL?
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT TO DO.
I FEEL LIKE I'M 10.
(rings clatter)
♪♪
(Guy) SO WE'RE HANGING OUT
IN ARLINGTON, TEXAS.
WE'RE AT A PLACE
CALLED THE CHOP HOUSE
EATING DYNAMITE BURGERS.
BUT NOW... WE'VE GOT
A SPECIAL TREAT.
WE'RE MAKING GUMBO.
BUT NOT JUST ANY GUMBO.
WE'RE MAKING IT WITH
EARL CAMPBELL'S HOT LINKS.
BUT NOT JUST HIS HOT LINKS.
EARL CAMPBELL'S
IN THE DINING ROOM,
WAITING TO TRY THE GUMBO.
AS A KID GROWING UP
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA,
YOU HAD
YOUR FAVORITE PLAYERS.
MINE JUST HAPPENED TO BE
THIS INCREDIBLE RUNNING BACK,
NUMBER 34,
FROM THE HOUSTON OILERS.
SO HE STARTS A SAUSAGE
AND MEAT COMPANY,
AND YOU START USING IT
IN YOUR GUMBO.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL
RIGHT HERE.
OH, YEAH.
LOOK AT THAT.
WE'RE GONNA START OUT
WITH SOME ONIONS.
OUR RED AND GREEN BELL PEPPERS.
AND OUR CELERY.
THE HOLY TRINITY.
BUT WE'RE REALLY NOT
GONNA SAUTÉ THEM.
I WANT KINDA CRUNCHY
IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
GOT SOME THYME. OREGANO.
GOT SOME CHILI POWDER.
THE BAY LEAVES.
A LITTLE BIT OF PAPRIKA.
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
NOT VERY MUCH CAYENNE.
AIN'T GONNA BE VERY SPICY.
NOT YET.
GRANULATED GARLIC. ALL RIGHT,
THEN WE GOT SOME CLAM BASE.
CHICKEN BASE?
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN BASE.
OKAY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
ALL OF OUR WATER.
ABOUT 3 GALLONS OF WATER.
JUST DUMP AND STIR?
DUMP AND STIR.
AND THEN YOU JUST LET IT GO
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
BUT NO COOKING THE SAUSAGE DOWN,
RENDERING OUT THE FAT?
NO, I ACTUALLY LIKE THE FAT
IN THERE.
WE PUT IT IN
AT THE VERY END.
ARE YOU GONNA PUT
A ROUX IN THERE?
YEAH, WE GOT
A DARK CHOCOLATE ROUX.
THAT'S ROUX-LICIOUS, DUDE.
LOOK AT THAT!
WHEN DOES THE SAUSAGE GO IN?
RIGHT AFTER THAT.
IF YOU DON'T HURRY UP
WITH IT,
IT'S GONNA BE DOWN
TO HALF A BATCH.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT, SO WE TAKE SOME
OF THE STOCK OUT OF THERE,
AND WE'RE GONNA TEMPER THE ROUX
WITH IT. GET A NICE STIR.
YOU'RE THINNING THAT ROUX
OUT A LITTLE BIT.
BRINGING IT UP TO TEMP.
AND IT REALLY--
TEMPERING THE ROUX KEEPS IT
FROM MAKING LITTLE DUMPLINGS.
DUMPLINGS.
YEAH.
IT'S TIDYING UP
REALLY NICE.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
THE SAUSAGE.
NEXT WE'LL TAKE OUR OKRA.
GUMBO FILÉ.
(New Orleans accent)
FILÉ GUMBO.
(normal voice) AND THEN
LAST BUT NOT LEAST...
CRAB MEAT. CRAWFISH.
NOW IT MAKES SENSE THAT YOU
PUT THAT CLAM BASE IN THERE.
STIR IT ALL UP NOW. HOW LONG
TILL WE'RE READY TO SERVE?
TEN MINUTES.
JUST TO GET
EVERYTHING WARM?
JUST BRING EVERYTHING
BACK UP TO TEMPERATURE.
SERVED OVER A LITTLE RICE.
THAT'S IT.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE JUICE.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S A CORNUCOPIA
OF VEGETABLES IN THERE.
I LIKE THE OKRA.
MMM!
(mouth full)
VEGGIES DO HAVE CRUNCH.
AND THEN THERE'S SOME OF THAT
SAUSAGE RIGHT THERE,
THAT EARL CAMPBELL SAUSAGE.
MMM!
HOW MUCH IS THAT?
$4.49.
DUDE, IN A BOWL PROBABLY
BIGGER THAN I CAN EAT?
$4.49?
IT'S A BARGAIN.
MMM!
COME ON DOWN.
(mouth full)
YOU'RE A ROCK STAR, MAN.
THANK YOU.
MAKE ME UP ANOTHER BOWL.
EARL'S WAITING.
ALL RIGHT.
THE BIG 'OLE BOWL OF GUMBO.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT GUMBO?
GOOD. CRAWFISH.
THAT SAUSAGE.
I THINK THE SAUSAGE
KICKS IT OFF.
THE CHEF MAY KNOW
WHAT HE'S DOING.
AND IT'S REAL-DEAL?
IT'S THE REAL DEAL.
YOU DO A GOOD JOB, THOUGH,
MAN, WITH YOUR SHOW.
YOU HELP A LOT OF PEOPLE, TOO.
MY MOM TOLD ME SOMETHING
ONE TIME.
IT TAKES A LOT TO BE
NASTY TO PEOPLE.
IT DON'T TAKE THAT MUCH
TO BE NICE TO THEM.
AND I'VE ALWAYS TRIED
TO REMEMBER THAT.
I CANNOT TELL YOU,
THIS IS, WITHOUT QUESTION,
ONE OF THE GREATEST MOMENTS
IN TRIPLE "D" HISTORY,
AND--AND ME PERSONALLY
AS JUST GUY FIERI, SO...
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WELL, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, MAN.
YOU'RE AWESOME.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH
LIST IS OVER FOR ME.
THAT'S--
YEAH, I HAVE TO CLIMB
A PYRAMID
AND RIDE A UNICORN,
THEN I'M DONE.
(both laugh)
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY!
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT WEEK
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
"NO, YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
THAT GUY THAT DOES
THE COOKING TIME
WITH THAT HAIR?"
THEN I SAY, "OH, MAN."
WE'RE REAL FANS, MAN.
ON FRIDAY NIGHT,
YOU'RE THE DEAL, MAN.
I WANT TO ASK YOU SOMETHING.
WHEN YOU'RE ON THAT SHOW--
LET ME JUST--
LET ME JUST BREATHE.
NO, NO, LISTEN.
LET ME JUST BREATHE
FOR A SECOND.
NO, LISTEN.
(laughs) THIS HAS BEEN
AMAZING.