HEY THERE, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
WHOA-OH-HO-HO-HO...
IT'S A COAST-TO-COAST
FLAVOR TOWN JOY RIDE.
IN CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA...
WE'RE IN THE SOUTH, DUDE.
AN OLD-SCHOOL
BREAKFAST SPOT...
BIG NEW HOTNESS.
DEFINITELY WORTH FIGHTING FOR.
(laughs) I'LL GIVE YOU
THAT ONE. YOU'RE THE FIRST.
(sizzling)
IN CHICAGO'S LINCOLN SQUARE...
LET'S JUST JUMP
RIGHT INTO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
THE GERMAN JOINT...
ONE FULL ORDER
WITH DUMPLINGS!
WITH A CHEF SO LEGIT,
THEY NAMED A STREET AFTER HIM.
OH, THIS IS AWESOME.
YOU'RE DOING A GREAT JOB
YOURSELF.
AND SOMEWHERE ON OAHU,
HAWAII...
YOU NEVER KNOW
WHERE SHE'S GONNA BE!
(laughing)
BAWK!
A 4-WHEELED RESTAURANT...
(whistles)
WITH A WHISTLE?
WITH A WHISTLE.
WITH BIG-TIME FLAVOR...
GET IT ON THERE!
AND A KILLER VIEW.
THIS IS A PACKAGE DEAL,
GIRL.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
(Hawaiian music playing)
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE "D,"
I ALWAYS TELL YOU
WHERE I'M GOING,
I TRY GREAT FOOD,
LET YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU CAN FIND THE LOCATION.
WELL, THIS TIME IT'S JUST GONNA
BE A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
YOU SEE, I'M ON
THE ISLAND OF OAHU,
I'M GONNA TRY SOME
GREAT FOOD... (hisses)
BUT I CAN'T REALLY TELL YOU
WHERE IT'S AT
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW
WHERE SHE'S GONNA BE!
THIS IS CAMILLE'S ON WHEELS.
MANGO PIE.
I BREAK MY DIETARY LAWS
A LOT FOR CAMILLE.
AND WHETHER SHE'S
PARKING IN THE CITY
OR AT THE BEACH...
CHIMICHURRI.
CAMILLE KOMINE'S FANS
MAKE SURE TO TRACK HER DOWN.
SHE HAS A GPS ON HER TRUCK.
SO SHE MIGHT JUST BE
IN SOME REMOTE LOCATION,
AND YOU'VE GOT A HANKERING
FOR CAMILLE'S ON WHEELS...
I DO.
AND YOU GO FIND IT.
I DO. I GET MY FIX.
HERE'S YOUR TACO.
YOU CAN ALWAYS TELL
WHERE SHE IS,
'CAUSE THERE'S ALWAYS
A LINE.
GOOD FOOD AND GOOD ATTITUDE.
DELIVERED FIVE TIMES A WEEK
BY CAMILLE...
THERE YOU GO.
A CALIFORNIA NATIVE
WHO COOKED IN SAN DIEGO
BEFORE GETTING INTO
THE MOVIE INDUSTRY.
I WAS A SET DECORATOR
AND A FOOD STYLIST.
I HIT MY WALL AND SAID,
"ENOUGH'S ENOUGH,
AND I WANT TO GO COOK AGAIN."
NOW SHE'S PRODUCING
BLOCKBUSTERS
OF A DIFFERENT KIND.
I LOVE HER MEAT LOAF.
MANGO PIE FOR ME, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
HER MANGO PIE IS TO DIE FOR.
AND WAIT TILL YOU CHECK OUT
THE MAIN ATTRACTION...
THE CHIMICHURRI BEEF TACO.
CAMILLE'S OWN
BIG ISLAND BLEND
OF HAWAIIAN
AND CALIFORNIA FLAVORS.
IT IS AWESOME.
SO WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE TODAY?
UH, CHIMICHURRI BEEF TACO.
WHAT ARE WE STARTING WITH?
WE'RE MAKING
CHIMICHURRI SAUCE.
READY? WE'VE GOT PARSLEY.
BIG BUNCH OF CILANTRO.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND THAT.
(whirs)
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME ONIONS.
ONE JALAPEÑO.
WHOLE. SEEDS, MEMBRANE.
WE'RE GONNA BLEND THAT UP.
(whirs)
THEN WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME GARLIC IN.
I LIKE GARLIC.
YOU LIKE GARLIC?
I'M A BIG FAN.
ALL RIGHT.
RED CHILI FLAKES.
CUMIN?
CUMIN.
MEXICAN OREGANO. YEAH.
VERY KEY.
YEAH.
BLACK PEPPER.
SALT. (whistles)
WITH A WHISTLE?
WITH A WHISTLE.
THEN WE'RE BLENDING THIS.
OKAY.
(whirring)
RED WINE VINEGAR.
LOTS OF IT.
AND OLIVE OIL.
GOOD TO GO.
YOU WANNA TRY THIS?
I'D LOVE TO.
ALL RIGHT.
(smacks lips)
AH, THAT'S NICE.
HASN'T EVEN HAD A CHANCE
TO MARRY THE FLAVORS YET.
YEAH.
SO GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT
MORE TIME TO COME TOGETHER.
OKAY, NOW WHAT PART?
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME PICO.
PICO DE GALLO.
AND "PICO DE GALLO" MEANS?
♪♪
PICK OF THE CHICKEN. NO.
THE BEAK OF THE ROOSTER.
SEE? I WAS CLOSE.
THE "PICK OF THE CHICKEN"?
(laughing)
BAWK!
WE GOT LOCAL TOMATOES.
WE GOT SOME ONIONS
AND LOTS OF JALAPEÑOS.
OKAY?
WHOA!
YEAH. DO SOME LIME.
OKAY.
A LITTLE SALT.
NOT TOO MUCH.
AND WE TOSS IT.
THAT IS A LOT OF JALAPEÑO.
YEAH, I LIKE IT HOT.
THAT'S LIKE JALAPEÑO SALSA.
(laughs) AND THERE WE HAVE IT.
VERY NICE.
OKAY.
SO WE GOT SOME SHORT RIB.
RIGHT? WE'RE GONNA
PUT IT ON A HOT...
(sizzling)
NO OIL, NOTHING?
NOTHING.
SO THERE'S ENOUGH FAT
IN THAT SHORT RIB
THAT IT'S JUST GONNA COOK
ON ITS OWN, HUH?
YEAH.
JUST A LITTLE GARLIC SALT.
SEAR THAT UP TO ABOUT MEDIUM.
I LOVE THIS.
I MEAN, TALK ABOUT
A WORK ENVIRONMENT.
LOOK AT THE VIEW.
YOU GOT YOUR OWN LITTLE
CASITA HERE.
I MEAN, THIS IS--
THIS IS CHILL.
IT'S GOOD.
HEY, LOOK AT THAT.
YEAH, IT'S GONNA BE NICE.
RIGHT ON. OKAY.
SO WHAT WE DO
IS WE CUBE THIS UP.
I SHOULD PROBABLY
JUST CHECK THAT.
YEAH!
JUST, I MEAN,
SCIENTIFIC REASONS.
MMM.
ALL RIGHT, WE TAKE
A LITTLE OF THIS.
OUR CHIMICHURRI
WE JUST MADE.
TOSS IT.
TWO CORN TORTILLAS.
GET IT ON THERE!
CHIMICHURRI BEEF.
A LITTLE CABBAGE.
A LITTLE CREMA DE
MIRIN MAYO.
JAPANESE COOKING WINE.
SWEET WINE.
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR
SPICY PICO DE GALLO.
FRESH CILANTRO.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
AT THE BEACH, AT THE STREET,
ANYWHERE YOU GO.
HMM-HMM.
YOU TAKE THAT
PIECE OF MEAT,
MAKE YOUR OWN
CHIMICHURRI.
MMM.
(mouth full) CABBAGE.
THE MIRIN CREMA.
MMM.
ALL THE COMPONENTS.
LOOK AT THAT--
I'M WEARING HALF OF IT.
(laughs)
MMM. DYNAMITE.
THANK YOU.
CHIMICHURRI BEEF TACO.
SPICY AND CRUNCHY.
YOU CANNOT REPLICATE THOSE
LAYERS OF FLAVOR AND THE SPICE.
SO THAT'S THE BEST WAY
TO FIND HER, IS TO GO ON--
IS TO FOLLOW HER ON TWITTER?
SHE ALSO HAS A FACEBOOK PAGE
AS WELL,
BUT TWITTER IS ABOUT
THE BEST WAY.
ALL RIGHT, I GOTTA SIGN UP.
THIS IS A PACKAGE DEAL,
GIRL.
(mouth full) AT THE BEACH,
IN THE PRESENCE OF THE ONE.
IT CAN'T GET ANY BETTER.
THANKS FOR ME HAVING ME.
AH, THANKS FOR COMING.
GOTTA COME FIND HER.
(man) TWO, THREE, FOUR!
UP NEXT...
♪ WELCOME TO THE BRAUHAUS
IN CHICAGO ♪
(chanting)
WE'RE HEADED TO CHICAGO,
FOR OOMPAH, STEIN,
AND A LITTLE SOMETHING
CALLED SAUERBRATEN.
(mouth full) I COULD
SIT HERE AND EAT THAT
LITERALLY UNTIL I WENT INTO
LIKE A FOOD COMA.
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I LOVE MEETING
THE REAL-DEAL,
OLD-SCHOOL SHOT-CALLER CHEFS.
I'M HERE IN CHICAGO
IN THE LINCOLN SQUARE AREA,
JUST A FEW MILES
FROM DOWNTOWN,
TO MEET A CHEF
THAT IS SO RECOGNIZED,
REGARDED, AND CELEBRATED,
THEY NAMED A STREET AFTER HIM
AND A PARK.
THIS IS WHERE IT HAPPENS.
THIS IS CHICAGO BRAUHAUS.
♪ WELCOME TO THE BRAUHAUS
IN CHICAGO ♪
(chanting)
IF YOU WANT GREAT GERMAN FOOD
IN CHICAGO,
YOU NEED TO COME
TO CHICAGO BRAUHAUS.
(man) ...TWO LEBERKAESE,
ONE WIENER SCHNITZEL.
ARE YOU OF GERMAN DESCENT?
I AM.
IS THIS AS GOOD AS HOME?
AS GRANDMA?
YES.
REALLY?
YEAH.
YES.
IN SOME RESPECTS, BETTER.
'CAUSE IT'S STRAIGHT
FROM THE KITCHEN
OF GERMAN TRANSPLANT
HARRY KEMPF...
ONE FULL ORDER
WITH DUMPLINGS!
WHOSE SELF-TAUGHT COOKING
SKILLS ARE LEGENDARY
IN THE LINCOLN SQUARE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
(Guy) HE DESERVES HAVING
A STREET NAMED AFTER HIM?
YES.
THE STREET REALLY IS
UNWORTHY.
THE MAN.
(woman) THE MAN.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU OWNED
THIS RESTAURANT?
WELL, I'VE BEEN ON THIS
STREET FOR 48 YEARS.
CRANKIN' OUT CLASSICS
LIKE THE PORK SHANK,
WIENER SCHNITZEL, AND THIS
UNIQUELY GERMAN DISH.
(Harry) SAUERBRATEN,
SPAETZLE.
♪♪
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
THIS IS, UH, CALLED
SAUERBRATEN.
AND THE SOUR COMES
FROM THE VINEGAR?
AND THE WINE.
(German accent)
YES.
(normal voice) LET'S JUST
JUMP RIGHT INTO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
WE START OUT
WITH THE ONIONS.
YOU ADD SOME CARROTS.
SOME CELERY.
SO REGULAR MIREPOIX.
FRESH GARLIC.
A LOT OF BAY LEAF.
A RIDICULOUS AMOUNT OF CLOVE.
SERIOUSLY?
YES.
PEPPERCORN.
AND SOME PEPPERCORN.
AND THEN FINALLY SOME
CINNAMON STICKS.
OKAY. THAT IS A VERY UNIQUE
CONCOCTION.
YES. THEN WE ADD THIS
WINE VINEGAR.
THEN WE ADD THIS
BURGUNDY WINE,
OR USUALLY I TAKE
WHATEVER'S LEFT
IN SOME BOTTLES,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YEAH. (chuckles)
IT ALL TASTES THE SAME,
YOU KNOW, SO...
AND HOW LONG AS WE GONNA
LET THIS MARINATE?
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
FIVE TO SIX DAYS.
WHAT?!
YEP.
SERIOUSLY?!
SERIOUSLY.
THIS HAS NOW BEEN
IN A MARINADE FOR FIVE DAYS.
THAT IS CRAZY.
WATCH OUT FOR A MINUTE.
I'M GONNA JUST PUT THAT
IN THERE.
SO BROWN ALL THE SIDES?
ALL SIDES, JA.
THAT'S A FIRE. AND THEN HOW ARE
WE GONNA FINISH THE COOKING?
I ALREADY MADE THE STOCK
FROM BONES,
CHICKEN, EVERYTHING
THAT CAME OUT.
I AM THEN NOW GONNA ADD...
CARAMELIZED SUGAR.
CARAMELIZED SUGAR, JA.
THE SEARED MEAT.
A FEW MORE CINNAMON STICKS.
CLOVES. BAY LEAVES.
SO HOW LONG DID THAT COOK?
THAT COOKED ABOUT
THREE HOURS, SLOW.
AND NOW WE GOT
THE FINISHED PRODUCT.
MAKE A NICE STRAIGHT CUT.
YOU CAN SEE HOW IT'S MARINATED
AND HOW IT'S COOKED, TOO.
IN THE MEANTIME, I HAVE
MY GRAVY ALL READY,
WHICH I MADE BEFORE.
PUT THIS IN.
THIS IS GONNA BE BANANAS.
THEN I'M TAKING
THESE TWO PIECES.
AND THEN WE FINISH
COOKING IT.
IN ANOTHER MINUTE OR SO,
WE'RE GOING TO BE ALL DONE.
WE READY?
WE ARE READY.
NOW YOU HAVE
BOTH PIECES ON THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
PUT SOME SPAETZLE ON HERE.
AND WE STRAIN IT?
WELL, IT JUST MAKES IT
NICE AND SHINY.
THERE YOU GO, SIR.
MMM.
(mouth full)
OH, MY GOSH, IT'S RICH.
IT'S TENDER, NOT DRY.
BIG FLAVOR WITH THE GRAVY.
OH, THIS IS AWESOME.
YOU'RE DOING
A GREAT JOB YOURSELF.
I COULD SIT HERE
AND EAT THAT
LITERALLY UNTIL I WENT INTO
LIKE A FOOD COMA.
REMINDS ME
OF GRANDMA'S KITCHEN.
GRAVY'S CRAZY. AND YOU JUST
WANT TO MAKE SURE
YOU DON'T HAVE IT
ALL OVER YOUR FACE.
(mouth full) MMM.
THAT AND THE CABBAGE.
ALL I NEED IS
A BIG STEIN OF BEER.
WE GOT THAT, TOO.
HUH?
HOW ABOUT THE BIG BOOTS?
HE KNUCKLE-BUMPED ME.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU.
I TOLD YOU THAT.
I'M LEARNING.
(laughter)
ON TO THE NEXT THING,
RIGHT?
UP NEXT...
(cheering)
IT'S LIKE OKTOBERFEST
EVERY DAY?
WE'RE BRINGING DOWN
THE HOUSE
AT CHICAGO BRAUHAUS...
(chanting)
WITH ANOTHER GERMAN DISH
JUST LOADED WITH SURPRISES.
SO, BACON, ONIONS,
THE SEASONING, AND THE PICKLE.
MWAH-HA!
♪♪
IN THE LINCOLN SQUARE
AREA OF CHICAGO,
CHEF HARRY KEMPF IS ALWAYS
CALLING THE SHOTS.
LET'S GO! ALSO PORK SHANK
WITH SPAETZLE.
AND YOU REALLY DO FEEL LIKE
YOU'VE TELEPORTED
INTO ANOTHER COUNTRY?
YES, ESPECIALLY
WHEN THE MUSIC'S PLAYING.
WE HAVE REGULAR DANCE MUSIC,
WE GOT, LIKE YOU SAY,
OOMPAH MUSIC, AND, UH...
OOMPAH! (laughs)
ARE YOU A GOOD DANCER?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M A BETTER MUSICIAN.
♪ WELCOME TO THE BRAUHAUS
IN CHICAGO ♪
THAT'S RIGHT. NOT ONLY DOES HE
KNOCK IT OUT OF THE PARK
WITH HIS FOOD, BUT THE DUDE
ROCKS IT ON THE BASS, TOO!
♪ BRAUHAUS IN CHICAGO ♪
(singing and chanting)
THIS PLACE IS JUST
OFF THE HOOK, CRAZY WILD,
IT'S LIKE OKTOBERFEST
EVERY DAY?
YES.
AND WHAT'S A GERMAN PARTY
WITHOUT MORE
TRADITIONAL GERMAN GRUB?
(chanting)
LIKE THIS OVERSIZED
BEEF ROLL-UP...
THE RINDSROULADEN.
MADE FROM A RECIPE
STRAIGHT OUT OF EAST PRUSSIA.
(sing indistinctly)
(cheering)
ALL RIGHT, CHEF,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NEXT?
THIS IS CALLED RINDSROULADE.
"RIND," R-I-N-D,
MEANS BEEF.
AND "ROULADE" EXPLAINS
ITSELF--ROLL.
ROLL.
RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, SO WE DO
SOME ROLLING HERE.
OKAY.
THIS IS THE TOP ROUND.
WE'RE GONNA SLICE
SOME NICE SLICES.
HERE WE GO.
OKAY, SO YOU POUND THIS OUT.
NOW... COMES
THE SEASONING AGAIN.
OKAY.
START OUT WITH SOME PEPPER.
SALT. A LITTLE PAPRIKA.
AND SOME VEGETA.
THIS IS, YOU KNOW,
DEHYDRATED PARSNIPS AND ALL
THAT KIND OF STUFF, YOU KNOW?
YEP.
MIX THIS UP A LITTLE BIT.
NOW, A LITTLE MUSTARD.
BY THE WAY, THIS IS GOOD
DUSSELDORF STYLE MUSTARD.
NOW COMES THE SEASONING.
THEN WE PUT A SLIP
OF BACON IN.
YOU SLICE THE BACON YOURSELF?
SLICE IT OURSELVES, YES.
VERY THIN SLICED ONIONS.
THEN COMES A NICE
KOSHER PICKLE.
'CAUSE PEOPLE THAT ARE
EATING THE KOSHER PICKLE
REALLY ENJOY THAT BACON
RIGHT IN THERE. (chuckles)
WE ROLL THIS UP LIKE THIS...
(whistles)
AND TIE THIS WITH A LITTLE
TOOTHPICK, AND THERE IT GOES.
THAT GOES IN THERE,
WE COVER IT UP,
AND COOK IT TILL IT'S DONE.
HOW LONG?
PROBABLY AN HOUR AND A HALF,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT, YEAH.
HOUR AND A HALF?
OKAY, NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A LITTLE DUCK ROUX HERE.
DUCK ROUX.
DUCK. YEAH.
WE'RE TAKING THE STOCK.
WE'RE DOING IT WITH DUCK FAT?
DUCK FAT.
WE HAVE SOME NICE FLOUR.
COOK OUT THE FLOUR.
RIGHT.
AND NOW WE ADD
JUST A LITTLE PAPRIKA.
WE MAKE THE GRAVY
WITH THE DRIPPINGS
AND THE DUCK FAT ROUX.
RIGHT.
OKAY. (clapping)
SO NOW WE GOT
OUR FINISHED PRODUCT.
THE BEEF ROULADEN.
WITH THE GRAVY MADE
WITH THE DUCK FAT ROUX.
THE DUCK FAT ROUX.
THE POTATO DUMPLINGS.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE, JA.
WOW. THAT'S TENDER.
I JUST HIT IT WITH THE FORK,
AND IT COMES APART.
THAT'S THE IDEA.
SO BACON, ONIONS, THE SEASONING,
AND THE PICKLE.
(laughs)
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
MMM. WOW, THAT IS
DIFFERENT.
SO HERE'S WHAT YOU GOT--
SUPER TENDER MEAT,
LOTS OF FLAVOR
FROM THE INSIDE OF THAT,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE DILL PICKLE FLAVOR.
MWAH-HA!
THE GRAVY IS OUTSTANDING.
I MEAN, IT'S A REALLY NICE,
RICH GRAVY.
MY KIDS WOULD LOVE THAT.
THIS HAS BEEN OUTSTANDING.
HEY...
THANK YOU.
GOOD GERMAN COMFORT FOOD.
HARRY PUTS HIS HEART INTO IT,
AND YOU CAN TASTE IT.
CHEF, HOW MUCH OF THIS
IS A JOB, AND HOW MUCH OF THIS
IS 'CAUSE YOU JUST LOVE IT?
ALL OF IT IS THAT I LOVE IT.
♪♪
UP NEXT...
I'M READY.
WE'RE HEADED TO CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA...
YOU SAID YOU LIKE
THE GRAVY, DID YOU?
FOR A BREAKFAST SPOT
BREAKING ALL THE RULES...
WHOA-OH!
YOU KNOW--
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO GET
CAUGHT HANGING OUT WITH YOU.
WHEN IT COMES TO
GETTING IT RIGHT.
YOU PULLED IT OFF, MAN.
♪♪
I'M HERE IN HISTORIC
CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA,
RIGHT OVER BY THE CENTRAL
MARKET, WHICH IS KINDA--
(man shouts indistinctly)
WHAT'S UP? WHICH IS KIND OF LIKE
THE HUB OF THE DOWNTOWN AREA.
NOW, OVER HERE ON STATE STREET,
TUCKED AWAY,
IS A COOL LITTLE PLACE
WITH A FUNKY NAME
THAT YOU MIGHT JUST FLY BY
IF YOU DON'T...
(tires screech)
SLOW DOWN
AND TAKE A LOOK AROUND.
THIS IS DIXIE SUPPLY
BAKERY & CAFE.
♪♪
THIS IS GOOD OLD SOUTHERN FOOD.
I'D CRAWL IN HERE TO EAT.
EVERYTHING HERE IS FRESH,
MADE FROM SCRATCH,
AND ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
'CAUSE FOR OWNERS
ALLEN AND KRIS HOLMES,
IT'S NOT THEIR FIRST RODEO.
WELL, I OWNED A BAKERY
FOR ABOUT NINE YEARS.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE WENT TO EUROPE
AND TRAVELED A LOT.
AND THEN, WHEN IT WAS TIME
FOR ALLEN TO RETIRE
AND, UM, GET A REAL JOB,
WE DECIDED WE WOULD
START THIS PLACE.
NICE LITTLE 24-HOUR HOBBY
YOU GOT YOURSELF INTO.
AND THEY HIRED
CHEF PATRICK WOODHAM
TO TAKE ON ALL THE COOKING.
HOW LONG YOU WORKED HERE?
UHH... 2 1/2 YEARS?
WOW. IS IT PAINFUL?
WE'RE BUSY. (laughs)
YOU'LL GET THE PEOPLE
THAT WORK
IN ALL THE RESTAURANTS
AROUND HERE.
THEY COME HERE FOR BREAKFAST
BEFORE THEY GO TO WORK.
THAT'S THE BIGGEST
TELLTALE YOU CAN GET.
IT'S REALLY NICE
TO HAVE A PLACE
THAT SERVES REALLY GOOD FOOD
OPEN FOR BREAKFAST.
SCRATCH-MADE FOOD
FOR BREAKFAST AND LUNCH?
EXACTLY.
VANILLA FRENCH TOAST
STUFFED WITH PEACHES.
DEFINITELY LIKE THOSE.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
IT'S JUST THE WAY I LIKE IT.
THE STATE STREET BISCUIT--
MY NEW FAVORITE BREAKFAST.
THIS BABY'S SOUTHERN
FROM TOP TO BOTTOM.
ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WHAT WE CALL
THE STATE STREET BISCUIT.
IT'S GONNA BE ALL-NATURAL
CHICKEN FRIED CHICKEN
OVER A HANDMADE BISCUIT.
OKAY. FIRST THINGS?
WE'RE GOING TO DREDGE
THE CHICKEN.
A.P. FLOUR RIGHT HERE.
CORNMEAL,
WHICH IS WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA FIND IN THE SOUTH.
LOOK AT THAT!
CELERY SEED RIGHT HERE.
AFTER THAT, WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
KOSHER SALT, OF COURSE.
ONION POWDER, GARLIC POWDER,
LOVELY PAPRIKA FOR SOME COLOR,
AND SOME TURMERIC.
NOW I'M GONNA MIX THIS.
THIS A BIG SELLER?
YES, SIR.
I MEAN, YES. YES.
I'M SORRY. IT'S JUST TRADITION.
I HAVE TO BE POLITE.
"SIR." YEAH, NO, THAT'S GOOD.
I'M ALSO A, UH,
KENTUCKY ADMIRAL,
SO YOU CAN CALL ME "ADMIRAL."
(laughs)
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND MAKE
OUR MIX. SIMPLE, THREE EGGS.
BETTY CROCKER CALLED.
SHE'S GONNA NEED THIS BACK.
WELL, ACTUALLY,
I STOLE IT FROM ONE OF THE--
ONE OF THE BARBIE TWIN DOLLS,
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THAT'S THE REAL FLAVOR FLAV.
YEAH.
THAT IS THE REAL
FLAVOR FLAV.
(laughs)
SO CHICKEN'S READY TO GO,
YOU GET THE DREDGE ON HERE,
GIVE IT A SECOND, LET IT
ABSORB SOME OF THE...
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
SOME OF THE FLOUR SO IT STICKS
TO IT A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
RIGHT.
SO, NEXT WHAT WE'RE GONNA GO
IS WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME GOOD OLD BACON FAT,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
ACTUALLY PAN-SEAR THAT.
NEXT UP, WE'RE GONNA
DO GRAVY.
SOME PANS, GET A POT.
THE SMALLER OF THE TWO POTS.
THE HEAVY CREAM.
ADD SOME MORE MILK.
WHAT I'M GONNA DO
INSTEAD OF USING A ROUX
IS I'M JUST GONNA USE A SLURRY.
CORNSTARCH.
USUALLY WHEN YOU SAY "SLURRY,"
I THINK CORNSTARCH.
YEAH.
SO WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A CORNSTARCH--
WHOA-OH-HO-HO-HO-HO.
YOU KNOW--
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO GET
CAUGHT HANGING OUT WITH YOU.
WE'RE IN THE SOUTH, DUDE.
YOU'RE NOT MAKING A ROUX.
YOU'RE MAKING A SLURRY
TO PUT INTO THIS GRAVY?
OH, WE'RE GONNA GET SHOT.
(speaks indistinctly)
I KNOW.
WE'RE OKAY. WE'RE GETTING--
YOU KNOW, JUST--
JUST A LITTLE
MIXING IT UP.
SO...
I'M READY.
(both laugh)
YOU GET THE GRAININESS
FROM THE BISCUIT
AND YOU GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT GRAININESS
FROM THE--FROM
ROUX-BASED GRAVIES.
I JUST WANTED
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
OKAY.
YEAH, ANYWAYS,
INTO THE GRAVY,
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND PUT
SOME GRANULATED ONION,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF CELERY SEED.
NOW THE THING IS WE GOT
THIS OTHER POT GETTING HOT
FOR--THIS IS GROUND
PORK SAUSAGE.
GONNA GET THAT IN THERE IN
A LITTLE BIT OF A ROCKET HEAT.
EVER-POPULAR SAGE.
GROUND PEPPER.
YOU CAN LET THAT RENDER DOWN.
SLURRY TIME IT IS, SIR.
YOU'RE SURE NOBODY'S
COMING FOR US, RIGHT?
GO.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT IT.
SLURRY IN. ALL RIGHT.
(grunts)
SO WE'RE GONNA BRING
ALL THE FLAVOR OFF
THE BOTTOM OF THAT PAN.
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'LL START TO TIGHTEN UP.
CHICKEN'S ALMOST DONE,
THEN WE'LL PLATE IT UP.
AND WE'RE GONNA GET
OUR BISCUIT SLICE ON.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE JUST A GOOD OLD
LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND JUST TOAST IT ALL.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR
CHICKEN FRIED CHICKEN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE PROVOLONE ON.
JUST A TOUCH OF THE SAUSAGE
GRAVY ON TOP OF IT.
AND YOU DO IT
WITH AN ICE CREAM SCOOP.
YEAH. YEAH. JUST A TOUCH.
TOP IT OFF. VOILÀ.
WE CALL IT A BISCUIT.
I'VE YET TO SEE ANYBODY
PICK IT UP.
(laughs)
I'LL GIVE YOU THAT ONE.
YOU'RE THE FIRST.
WELL...
HMM. IT'S NICE. IT'S RICH.
IT'S MORE THAN A BREAKFAST ITEM.
I LIKE THE CHICKEN IN IT.
LOOK AT THAT. WITH CHEESE ON IT?
THAT HAS TO BE A STRONG
BISCUIT TO BE ABLE
TO WITHSTAND ALL THIS.
ALTHOUGH THE GRAVY HAS...
(whispers)
CORNSTARCH IN IT...
(normal voice)
YOU CAN'T TELL.
IT'S JUST A LIGHTER, THINNER,
BUT STILL--
STILL RICH CONSISTENCY.
YOU PULLED IT OFF, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
SAUSAGE GRAVY ON TOP OF IT
IS SO GOOD.
YOU SAID YOU LIKE
THE GRAVY, DID YOU?
(laughing)
MM-HMM!
IT'S GREAT TO SEE
THAT YOU'RE TAKING
ALL THE SOUTHERN SPECIALTIES.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT
FOR US.
AND, UH, WE DEVELOP NEW THINGS.
LIKE BOURBON BACON
PECAN PIE...
(mouth full) THIS IS AS GOOD
AS IT SOUNDS.
TOMATO PIE...
HEIRLOOM TOMATOES AND CHEESE
AND LOTS OF LOVE.
OR THEIR FRESH TAKE
ON THE B.L.T.
THE SHRIMP B.L.T. IS GREAT.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES,
SHRIMP, AND BACON.
'CAUSE THIS IS
THE NEW HOTNESS IN THE SOUTH.
BIG NEW HOTNESS.
BUTTERING THE WHEAT BERRY BREAD.
GET THAT TOASTED.
WHEAT BERRY BREAD?
THE SAME PEOPLE THAT ARE
GONNA BE LOOKING
FOR YOU AND ME
'CAUSE OF THE SLURRY
GONNA BE LOOKIN' 'CAUSE OF
THE WHEAT BERRY BREAD.
I DON'T SEE ANY HORSES
YET, DO YOU?
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO NOW
IS WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND MAKE OUR DREDGE
FOR THE FRIED GREEN TOMATOES.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
SOME A.P. FLOUR.
A LITTLE CORNMEAL.
ONCE AGAIN, CORNMEAL.
A LITTLE TEXTURE.
ABSOLUTELY.
THEN WE GET A LITTLE
GARLIC POWDER.
PAPRIKA JUST, AGAIN,
FOR COLOR.
KOSHER SALT
AND FINE GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
MIX IT UP.
WE'VE GOT THE DREDGE MADE.
MAKE A LITTLE WASH.
ONCE AGAIN, A GOOD OLD
THREE EGG.
NOW, IN A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF A SOUTHERN CLASSICAL TWIST,
WE'RE GONNA DO BUTTERMILK.
CAN YOU FIND GREEN TOMATOES
AROUND YEAR-ROUND
AROUND HERE?
YEAH, YOU CAN.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA DO, YOU
KNOW, A TRADITIONAL SLICE NOW.
WE'RE GONNA DO A DRY-WET-DRY.
RIGHT BEHIND YOU, WE'RE GONNA
GO TO A DEEP FAT FRY ON THIS.
SEE THAT MOVE?
WE'RE GONNA LET 'EM SWIM
A LITTLE BIT.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES DOWN.
THE BREAD'S TOASTING.
SO THESE SHRIMP,
THEY ARE TOTALLY FRESH?
YEAH. IT'S RIGHT
AT OUR DOORSTEP.
THAT'S NUTS.
GET THE HEAD OFF.
FIX THAT TAIL.
YOU WANT TO DEVEIN IT?
AND YOU GET YOUR PAN
NICE AND HOT.
(sizzling)
THAT'S A LOT OF SHRIMP.
WE'RE GONNA GET THAT GOING.
OKAY.
ONE OF MY PET PEEVES--
DON'T OVERCOOK THE SEAFOOD.
LAST THING THAT SHOULD BE
GETTING COOKED.
YEAH. OH, THE SHRIMP.
TAKE THAT WHEAT BERRY BREAD.
GET THE MAYONNAISE.
CRISP ROMAINE. YOU GOTTA
HAVE SOME SUPPORT HERE.
YOU CAN DO IT.
YOU CAN DO IT. COME ON.
I THINK SO, MAN.
I'M WORKING HARD.
YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
AND THEN--
IS THAT THE KIND OF SUPPORT
HE WANTED?
THEN YOU WANT TO TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF BACON.
NOW, THE REASON YOU DO
THE BACON THERE
IS 'CAUSE IT GIVES IT
A NICE, SOUND FOUNDATION
FOR ALL THIS HERE.
YOU GET SOME GREEN TOMATOES.
JUST A TOUCH MORE SALT.
HERE WE GO.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF A SANDWICH.
(mouth full) I MEAN,
THE SHRIMP ON ITS OWN, MAN.
YEAH.
THEY'RE SUPER FRESH,
PERFECTLY COOKED.
FRIED GREEN TOMATOES--
WHEN YOU'RE IN THE REGION
AND YOU'RE TRYING
THE BOUNTY OF THE COUNTY...
HMM, THAT'S IT.
BREAD'S NICE AND TOASTY.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF MAYO.
LET THE NATURAL FLAVORS
COME TOGETHER.
THIS IS TRULY AN INDULGENT
SANDWICH.
IF YOU'RE A LUMBERJACK--
YOU KNOW, IF YOU HAPPEN
TO BE WORKING HERE...
RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS YOUR SANDWICH.
YEAH.
(crunches)
THERE IS ENOUGH BACON ON THAT,
YOU COULD SINK A TUGBOAT.
MM-HMM.
(chuckles) LOOK, SHE'S--
I LOVE BACON.
IT JUST DOESN'T GET
ANY BETTER.
EVERYBODY HUNTS THE PLACE OUT.
LIKE YOU'RE AT YOUR
DINING ROOM TABLE.
DIG IT.
(laughs)
WHAT A FUNKY PLACE.
TINY, TOO.
HOW MANY TABLES YOU GOT
IN HERE, SIX?
WELL, THAT'S A KIND OF
A DOUBLE TABLE BACK THERE.
WHOO.
(laughs)
BETTER BE READY TO SHARE.
THANKS FOR HAVING US,
YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU.
♪♪
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE
TRIPLE "D" JOINTS
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY!
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT WEEK
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
WATCH THIS.
(spraying)
WHOO! PARTY AT MY HOUSE!
YEAH! YOO!
(laughter)