HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(laughing) WHAT IS
GOING ON?
IT'S A FOOD FOOT RACE...
(Guy) SHE'S GONNA KILL ME!
AND WE'RE PASSING THE BATON.
IN VENTURA, CALIFORNIA...
IT'S A PERFECT STORM.
A ROCKIN' BREAKFAST HOUSE...
(laughing)
KEEPING THE PAST ALIVE
IN NAME...
"IT'S GOT MY NAME ON IT.
I'VE GOTTA BUY IT."
MM.
AND IN FLAME.
KIND OF LIKE HANGING
CHRISTMAS LIGHTS ON A MISSILE.
(strained voice) WHOA!
(laughter)
AND BALTIMORE, MARYLAND,
THE LANDMARK DINER...
YOU'RE WEARING FLIP-FLOPS
ON THE EAST COAST!
WHAT IS THIS, CALI?
GOING ON THEIR THIRD GENERATION
OF GREEK COMFORT FOOD...
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
I GOTCHA.
MONSTER CRAB CAKES...
I WON'T BE ABLE TO LEAVE
AFTER THIS.
(laughs)
AND A SIDE ORDER OF ATTITUDE.
(Guy) IT IS THE GREEK
LUCY AND RICKY SHOW!
THIS MIGHT BE ONE OF
THE FUNNIEST EVER.
I SHOULD HAVE GOTTEN HIM--
OH, MY GOSH!
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ONE "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES"!
♪♪
I'M HERE IN VENTURA, CALIFORNIA,
ABOUT 50 MILES NORTH
OF LOS ANGELES.
NOW REMEMBER WHEN YOU WERE
A KID,
YOU USED TO PLAY THE GAME,
"PETE AND RE-PETE
"WERE SITTING ON A FENCE.
PETE FELL OFF.
WHO WAS LEFT? RE-PETE"?
I MEAN, I PLAY IT WITH RYDER
ALL THE TIME.
WELL, I GOT A JOINT HERE THAT
WAS OWNED BY A DUDE NAMED PETE.
AND THEN HE SELLS IT.
WHO'S HE SELL IT TO?
ANOTHER DUDE NAMED PETE.
WELL, HE'S NOT SITTING
ON A FENCE.
NO, HE OWNS A BREAKFAST JOINT.
THIS IS PETE'S BREAKFAST HOUSE.
(British accent)
SPANISH OMELET, OLIVE.
EVERYTHING HERE
TASTES VERY HOMEMADE.
BREAKFAST ALL DAY,
AND IF YOU'RE LUCKY,
YOU'LL FIND A SEAT.
I HAVE THE BISCUIT PLATE
FOR YOU.
IT'S DEFINITELY MADE
FROM SCRATCH.
HOW'S YOUR BREAKFAST JOINT?
THE BEST. NOT ONLY
THE BEST IN TOWN,
MAYBE THE BEST
IN CALIFORNIA.
THANKS TO HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
PETE AND LYNDSAY TIMPSON...
PETER, CHORIZO BURGER.
(British accent) THANK YOU.
TWO ENGLISH TRANSPLANTS
LIVING THEIR AMERICAN DREAM.
WAS IT A COINCIDENCE YOU FOUND
A PLACE CALLED PETE'S?
WHEN THEY TOLD ME WHAT THE NAME
WAS, IT WAS KIND OF A DONE DEAL.
"I GOTTA GO."
HE SAID, "IT'S GOT MY NAME
ON IT. I'VE GOTTA BUY IT."
SINCE THEN, THEY'VE BEEN
CRANKIN' OUT STUFF
THIS BREAKFAST JOINT
IS KNOWN FOR...
OLIVE, PANCAKE ROLL,
EXTRA FRUIT!
LIKE THIS CREAMY CREATION.
PANCAKE ROLL!
VERY, VERY GOOD.
LET'S MAKE PANCAKES.
THIS IS KING ARTHUR FLOUR.
IT'S THE SMOOTHEST FLOUR
ON THE PLANET.
NOT TO DO WITH ANY
ENGLISH THING?
WELL, THERE'S THAT, TOO.
YEAH.
SUGAR?
SUGAR, BUDDY.
SALT. BAKING POWDER.
A LITTLE BICARBONATE?
NOT TOO MUCH.
MAKES IT TOO DRY.
SO I'M GOING ON
TO THE WET SIDE OF THIS.
WHIPPED EGGS, BUTTERMILK,
MILK,
LITTLE BIT
OF MELTED BUTTER.
PANCAKES BIG IN ENGLAND?
THEY DO THOSE LITTLE
FAKE LITTLE CREPE-Y THINGS.
THE WET INTO THE DRY.
CAN YOU HOLD THAT BOWL?
YES.
YOU'RE A GOOD MAN.
JUST DON'T GET IT ON ME.
GET AFTER IT.
OH, GUY!
WHAT DO YOU WANT? YOU TOLD ME
TO HOLD THE BOWL.
YOU GOT OUT OF CONTROL.
YOU HAVE A LICENSE
FOR THIS? (whistles)
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW,
TO MAKE IT RISE UP,
I'M GONNA PUT SOME SPRITE
IN HERE.
REALLY? SO A LITTLE
LEMON-LIME SODA?
YEAH.
SO YOU GET THE SUGAR,
YOU GET THE BICARBONATE.
EVERYTHING THAT WE SHOULD
NEED, RIGHT.
I'M GONNA PUT THIS
IN THE WALK-IN,
LET IT REST
FOR ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
OKAY.
SO IT RISES, DOUBLES IN SIZE.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR GRANOLA FROM SCRATCH.
MMM! I WAS--I WAS RAISED
ON GRANOLA.
WAS YOUR MOTHER A VERY
FORWARD-THINKING WOMAN?
NO, MY PARENTS WERE HIPPIES.
THIS WAS ALWAYS SOMETHING
THAT WAS REALLY CRITICAL TO ME,
AND I PUT MYSELF A LITTLE BIT
IN THAT GRANOLA AFICIONADO.
LET'S SEE IF I CAN
IMPRESS YOU.
OKAY. LET'S START IT OFF.
OLD-FASHIONED ROLLED OATS,
SO THEY'RE NICE AND THICK.
OKAY. NONE OF THOSE NEWFANGLED
ROLLED OATS.
PECANS.
WALNUTS.
ALMONDS.
THERE IS MORE WEIGHT
IN NUTS
THAN THERE ARE
IN ROLLED OATS.
IT'S TRUE.
THIS IS GONNA BE
SOME RIGHTEOUS GRANOLA.
ZEST OF ORANGE. NUTMEG.
HONEY.
FRESH-SQUEEZED ORANGE.
(whistles)
THIS IS OUR
HOMEMADE SYRUP--
MAPLE SYRUP--
GOING IN THERE NOW.
SO YOU HAVE A TREE?
YOU HAVE A MAPLE TREE?
I DO.
WE SHIN UP IT.
YOU WHAT IT?
WE SHIN UP THE TREE,
AND WE GET THE... (laughs)
UM, I-I--
HANG ON. I'LL FIGURE OUT
WHAT SHE'S TALKING ABOUT.
STICK WITH ME.
WE... (laughs) WE SHIN--
SHOW ME THAT AGAIN.
WE SHIN UP THE TREE.
GOTTA GET THE LEGS GOING.
COME ON!
I'M GONNA FLY AWAY. WHAT IS--
WHAT--WHAT IS GOING ON?
(laughing)
(laughter)
MELTED BUTTER. LET'S ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER TO IT.
OKAY, TO HELP MIX
EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
YEAH.
AND NOW I'M GONNA
GET INTO THIS.
MAYBE A SMALLER BOWL
NEXT TIME.
WELL... (laughs)
HOW LONG IS IT GONNA GO
IN THE OVEN FOR?
IT'S GONNA GO IN THE OVEN
FOR THREE HOURS.
WHAT TEMP?
225.
OKAY, LET'S MAKE
THE PANCAKES.
THIS IS MY MONSTER PANCAKE.
THAT'S A BIG CAKE.
(mouth full) LOVE 'EM.
NOW YOU CAN'T SPEAK,
'CAUSE YOU'VE GOT A MOUTHFUL.
(speaking indistinctly
with mouth full)
THAT IS SOME RIGHTEOUS,
RIGHTEOUS GRANOLA.
I'M GONNA FLIP IT NOW.
OH, WAIT A SECOND.
(drumming rapidly)
(laughing)
(slaps surface)
YEAH!
THERE YOU GO!
WOW!
VANILLA YOGURT, AND I'M GONNA
TAKE SOME FRESH MIXED BERRIES.
GOTTA BE FRESH, GOTTA BE GOOD,
GOTTA BE JUICY.
THERE'S NO WAY WE COULD PUT
ANY MORE ON IT.
MORE VANILLA YOGURT,
AND...
MORE FRESH BERRIES ON TOP.
SCOOP OF OUR GREAT GRANOLA.
THERE YOU GO--
PANCAKE ROLL.
HMM. WOW.
(mouth full)
THE ACID OF THE YOGURT
AND THEN THE SWEETNESS
OF THE BERRIES,
THE SPONGINESS
OF THE PANCAKE,
BUT THEN THE CRUNCH
OF THE GRANOLA ON TOP OF IT--
I MEAN, IT'S A PERFECT STORM.
AND EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT
I'M NOT A HUGE BREAKFAST FAN.
WITHOUT QUESTION, I WOULD
ORDER THAT IN A HEARTBEAT.
IF YOU'RE COMING TO PETE'S,
YOU REALLY GOTTA TRY
THE PANCAKE ROLL.
IT'S LIKE A PARFAIT
ON A PANCAKE.
IT'S JUST A GREAT COMBINATION
OF FLAVORS.
PETE'S IS JUST
A GREAT PLACE TO BE.
BREAKFAST EVERY SUNDAY MORNING
FOR THE LAST 15 YEARS.
(sizzling)
SERVED UP BY THE SAME FOLKS
THAT WORKED
FOR THE ORIGINAL PETE--
LIKE Z, WHO'S BEEN
DISHING IT OUT FOR 15 YEARS,
AND GILBERT, WHO'S BEEN
COOKING IN THE BACK FOR 24.
IT'S JUST LIKE
BEING AT HOME.
SO WHEN THE TIMPSONS
TOOK OVER,
THEY STUCK TO THE BREAKFAST
BASICS.
THEY KEPT IT JUST ROLLING. THEY
DIDN'T CHANGE THE MENU MUCH.
BUT THEY DID SPICE UP THE MENU
FOR THE MIDDAY CROWD.
AND THE CHORIZO BURGER.
YEAH, THIS IS ON FIRE.
(whistles)
THAT LOOKS SPICY.
I'M GONNA PUT BOILED
TOMATOES IN THIS,
BOILED HABANEROS,
BOILED JALAPEÑOS,
AND TOP OF THAT,
ROASTED...
LET ME HEAR YOU SAY IT.
CHILE...
DE ARBOL, AND SALT.
READY TO ROCK 'N' ROLL?
(lowered voice) THIS IS
GONNA BE SO STRONG.
STAND BACK.
(whirring)
(splashing)
WITH A MIXTURE LIKE THAT,
YOU COULD REFINISH FURNITURE.
(whirs)
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S THE RIVER
THAT FLOWS OUT OF MOUNT VESUVIUS
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
GOT SOME FRESH-CUT
CILANTRO IN THERE.
WHY?
YOU SHOULD JUST DROP IN
LIKE 2 OR 3 QUARTS
OF PEPTO-BISMOL.
WE SELL IT ON THE WAY OUT.
FINALLY, CHOPPED ONION.
AND THERE WE GO.
HOW LONG DO YOU LET THAT
SET UP?
I'LL PUT IT IN THE WALK-IN
FOR ABOUT ONLY AN HOUR.
I MEAN, I LIKE HOW YOU--
YOU PLAY WITH IT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE HANGING
CHRISTMAS LIGHTS ON A MISSILE.
SO YOU'RE FAKING PEOPLE OUT--
"OH, LOOK! GREEN!
"THAT'S NOT GONNA BE SUPER
MELT-YOUR-TONGUE-
OUT-OF-YOUR-MOUTH HOT!"
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT.
LET ME TRY THIS.
DON'T.
IT'LL RUIN YOUR DAY.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
MM?
IT SMELLS LIKE JET FUEL.
WHAT DO YOU GUYS THINK?
TRY IT... OR DON'T TRY IT?
(sighs)
(gasping)
AND WE'LL BE BACK
RIGHT AFTER THESE MESSAGES.
I DON'T KNOW. SERIOUSLY,
I MIGHT TRY IT.
♪♪
WELCOME BACK. WE'RE AT PETE'S
IN VENTURA, CALIFORNIA,
AND THE QUESTION IS,
WILL I TRY IT OR NOT?
IT'S ALMOST EATEN THROUGH
THE CHIP.
IT HAS CORROSIVE
QUALITIES.
(laughs)
YOU DON'T HEAR THAT
EVERY DAY ON A MENU.
BACK UP A LITTLE BIT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
RIGHT IN ON TOP OF MY PAIN!
THE PROBLEM WITH THIS IS
THAT YOU'RE EVEN SAYING
IT'S A BAD IDEA.
WHY DO YOU MAKE IT?
(laughs) BECAUSE I'M GOING
TO GIVE IT TO YOU
TO ENHANCE
A CHORIZO BURGER.
OH. WELL, I DIDN'T KNOW
I'M GONNA... (British accent)
ENHANCE ANYTHING.
(normal voice) WHAT DO YOU GUYS
THINK AT HOME? GO FOR IT?
THANKS.
TAKE A BIG SCOOP THEN.
DON'T BE A WUSS.
(crunching)
(laughing)
(strained voice) OH...
(laughter)
OHH!
YOU PUT THAT ON FOOD?
OHH! WHOA!
I, UH... IS MY WHOLE
TONGUE IN THERE?
(laughter)
OHH! NOW IT'S INVADING
THE REST OF MY MOUTH!
(laughter)
SCOOBY-DOO DOES IT
THAT WAY.
(coughs) WHAT'S NEXT?
THE BURGER?
THE CHORIZO BURGER.
(sighs) OH, GOOD, LET'S MAKE
THE REST OF THE HOT FOOD NOW.
IT'S AN ENGLISH DISH?
SURELY.
DON'T CALL ME "SHIRLEY."
(laughs)
MY PARTNER COOK--
HE'S FROM OAXACA.
GOT THE BEST TASTE SENSE
IN THE WORLD.
OKAY. GET IT STARTED.
RED HOT CHILI PEPPER.
(whistles)
CAYENNE.
HOW MANY POUNDS OF MEAT
TO THE 1/4 CUP OF CAYENNE
YOU JUST PUT IN THERE?
TRIO. THREE. TRES.
PAPRIKA. BLACK PEPPER.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
MEXICAN OREGANO.
WHICH IS A WHOLE DIFFERENT THING
THAN REGULAR ITALIAN OREGANO.
CHECK IT OUT.
SALT,
TAD OF SUGAR
GOING IN THERE.
IT'S SECRET SPICES
FROM US.
LET ME TASTE IT.
(sniffs)
(smacks lips)
(whispers inaudibly)
NO.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
THAT HELPS THE CREDIBILITY.
"HOW ABOUT THAT?" "NO."
"HOW ABOUT THIS?" "MNH-MNH."
(laughter)
"HOW ABOUT THAT?"
"OKAY, HOW ABOUT NOT?"
WELL, THERE'S PEPPER,
THERE'S GRANULATED GARLIC,
THERE'S GRANULATED ONION.
CUMIN.
AND THERE'S GOT TO BE
A LITTLE BIT OF...
CELERY--
CELERY--CEL--YEP.
CUMIN, CELERY STICK. YEAH.
IT'S NOT A SECRET NOW.
WE WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
NO, WE WON'T TELL ANYBODY.
DON'T TELL ANYBODY THAT.
VINEGAR.
APPLE CIDER?
APPLE CIDER. GIVES IT
A LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS.
A LITTLE SWEET
AND A LITTLE BITE.
YEAH.
AND THIS IS CHILI WATER...
REALLY?
THAT I PULLED OFF FROM WHERE
I BOILED SOME HABANEROS
AND OTHER CHILIES.
SHE SAYS THAT WITH A DEVIOUS
LITTLE SMIRK.
LOOK AT HOW LOVELY THAT
LOOKS. DON'T YOU THINK?
MM-HMM.
AND THIS IS PORK BUTT,
AND I'VE HAD HIM
GRIND IT
COARSELY FOR ME...
OKAY.
SO I DON'T LOSE
ALL THE TEXTURE.
ADD MY CHORIZO MIX,
MAKE SURE IT'S ALL MIXED IN
REALLY, REALLY WELL.
I'M GONNA COVER IT, PUT IT
IN THE WALK-IN OVERNIGHT.
LET THE FLAVORS MARRY.
TAKE A PORTION OF THAT,
PUT IT IN THAT BOWL.
SO WE'RE GOING 50/50
BEEF TO CHORIZO?
50/50.
GOT IT.
THEN I'M GONNA PUT
OUR SPE--
(whispering)
SP-SPECIAL...
IT'S EASY FOR YOU TO SAY.
MORE CILANTRO.
AND WHEN YOU ADD
THE GROUND BEEF TO THIS,
IT TAKES OUT THE INTENSITY.
YOU ALSO ADD
SOME REALLY GOOD FAT.
YEAH, SO WHAT YOU GET LEFT WITH
IS JUST INCREDIBLE FLAVOR.
PATTY IT UP.
SO WE'RE GOOD.
BEAUTIFUL. ON TO THE FLAT TOP.
(sizzling)
PUT THE SOUR CREAM.
AS OPPOSED TO MAYONNAISE?
MAYONNAISE MAKES IT END UP
TASTING WAY TOO SWEET.
HABANERO SALSA.
SORRY.
(forced laugh)
(laughs)
LETTUCE.
NOW FOR THE GOOD STUFF.
AND THEN WE GOT FOUR SLICES
OF AVOCADO ON THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
I THINK EVERYBODY JOINS IN
TOGETHER
AT HOME WITH ME AND SAYS,
NOTHING LOOKS BETTER
WHEN GUY IS ON
TRIPLE "D,"
EATING A BITE OF A BIG,
SPICY, HOT, JUICY BURGER
THAN TO HAVE THE CHEF
DO IT WITH ME.
(laughs)
ONE, TWO, THREE.
MMM!
(mouth full) THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S HOT.
(strained voice) WHOA!
CAN SOMEBODY GET
THE FIRE EXTINGUISHER?
(mouth full) PROBABLY ONE
OF THE HOTTEST--
(laughing)
HOTTEST THINGS I'VE HAD
IN A WHILE.
THE FLAVOR
IS OUT OF BOUNDS!
AND THAT'S A REAL POWERFUL,
AUTHENTIC CHORIZO.
CUTTING IT WITH A LITTLE
BURGER--I LOVE IT.
THE DEVIL SALSA--I MEAN,
THAT'S REALLY, REALLY HOT.
MY EYELIDS ARE SWEATING.
BUT IT IS GREAT.
WE NAILED IT, RIGHT?
OH, YOU NAILED IT
TIMES TEN.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE CRAZY.
NOW HAVE HER ARRESTED.
IF YOU HAVEN'T HAD THIS BURGER,
YOU HAVE TO TRY IT.
IT'S FLAVORFUL.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
HOT SALSA.
SPICY?
VERY SPICY.
FUNKY LITTLE JOINT, PLAN ON
WAITING, BUT WORTH IT
WHEN YOU GET IN HERE, 'CAUSE
EVERYTHING'S SCRATCH-MADE.
BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
I HOPE THAT THE PEOPLE
WATCHING THIS
LIVE OUT OF TOWN,
BECAUSE THE CROWDS HERE
ARE ALREADY OFF THE HOOK.
(clapping)
(laughter)
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS,
'CAUSE THIS IS REALLY SERIOUS.
WHY ISN'T IT CALLED
"RE-PETE'S"?
'CAUSE IT WOULD COST MONEY
TO CHANGE THE SIGN.
I GOT A PEN!
(laughter)
JUST WRITE "RE" WRITE THERE.
THAT'S ALL IT NEEDS!
'KAY, WHEN YOU GUYS COME DOWN
HERE AND CHECK THIS JOINT OUT,
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT,
BUT YOU MAKE SURE
IT SAYS "PETE'S..."
"AND RE-PETE'S."
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO BALTIMORE, MARYLAND...
I'LL JUST TRY THIS
FOR YOU GUYS.
FOR A THIRD-GENERATION DINER...
THIS IS THE WAY GRANDPA
TAUGHT YOU?
THAT'S THE WAY WE DO IT.
OKAY.
THAT'S FLIPPIN'
A KILLER CRAB CAKE.
(mouth full) YOU GIVE ME,
LIKE, THE WHOLE CRAB BOAT.
OPA!
(laughter)
♪♪
ALL RIGHT, THIS ONE'S
A MOUTHFUL.
I'M IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND,
ON BOSTON STREET,
RIGHT BETWEEN
TWO NEIGHBORHOODS
OF CANTON AND FELLS POINT.
I'M AT A JOINT WHERE
A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
ARE RUNNING A THIRD-GENERATION
DINER
THAT'S OPEN 24/7, AND THEY'RE
SCRATCH-MAKING EVERYTHING.
THIS IS SIP & BITE.
ONE LAMB GYRO COMING UP.
THANK YOU.
IT'S DEFINITELY
A BALTIMORE LANDMARK.
YOU'RE FROM BALTIMORE,
YOU KNOW ABOUT THE SIP & BITE.
'CAUSE SINCE 1948...
SANTORINI.
THE VASILIADES FAMILY HAS BEEN
GIVING THE PEOPLE OF CHARM CITY
WHAT THEY WANT.
SPANAKOPITA.
THANK YOU.
THAT'S THREE GENERATIONS
STRONG SO FAR,
FROM GRANDPA TONY,
TO HIS SON GEORGE,
TO HIS KID TONY,
WHO NOW RUNS THE 24-HOUR JOINT
WITH HIS WILD WIFE SOFIA.
WE ARE FROM THE SAME
LITTLE MOUNTAIN IN GREECE.
FAMILIES KNEW EACH OTHER, SO...
THANKS FOR SHOWING ME
"MOUNTAIN."
LITTLE MOUNTAIN,
TOGETHER,
THEY'RE SERVING UP
CLASSIC GREEK DISHES...
PASTITSIO.
FAMILY RECIPES...
GYRO COMING UP.
AND SINCE THIS IS
IN MARYLAND,
YOU KNOW THEY GOTTA HAVE
CRAB CAKES.
GRILLED CRAB CAKE
PLATTER, SIR.
ABOUT THE BEST I EVER TASTED.
YOU'VE GOT THE CRAB CAKE
RECIPE DOWN.
YEAH.
THIS IS FROM MY GRANDFATHER--
60 YEARS RE--
SO THE SAME RECIPE?
YEAH, THE SAME.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
SO WHITE BREAD
THAT IS CUBED.
NO CRUST.
GOT IT.
THEN WE GO WITH
A LITTLE FRESH CRAB MEAT.
WE USE ABOUT 5 POUNDS.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO BREAK IT UP,
'CAUSE YOU WANT
BIG LUMPS OF CRAB.
THEN WE GO WITH
THE BIG BOY HERE.
THIS IS JUMBO LUMP.
YEAH.
I'LL JUST TRY THIS
FOR YOU GUYS,
MAKE SURE IT'S OKAY.
(mouth full)
I'M GOOD WITH THAT.
THE LUMP HAS MUSTARD,
WHICH HAS A LITTLE BIT MORE
FLAVOR TO IT. THAT'S--
THERE'S A LITTLE MUSTARD
MIXED INTO IT?
YEAH. IN THE LUMP, YEAH.
AND WHAT KIND OF CRAB
IS THIS--BLUE CRAB?
BLUE CRAB, YES.
SO THAT'S 10 POUNDS OF CRAB
TO THAT LITTLE AMOUNT OF BREAD.
THEN WE GO
WITH OUR MAYONNAISE.
ANY PARTICULAR KIND?
HEAVY DUTY.
HEAVY DUTY?
YEAH. (laughs)
I THINK THAT'S ONLY
IN TRUCK COMMERCIALS, BRO.
(laughs)
HEAVY DUTY MAYONNAISE!
MUSTARD.
AND YOU MIX ALL OF THIS
INDIVIDUALLY,
AS OPPOSED TO PUTTING
THE DRY INGREDIENTS
AND THE MAYONNAISE
AND THE MUSTARD
AND THE EGGS ALL TOGETHER
THEN MIXING THAT ALL TOGETHER?
YES.
THIS IS THE WAY
GRANDPA TAUGHT YOU?
THAT'S THE WAY WE DO IT.
OKAY.
OKAY, SO WE USE THE WET MUSTARD
AND DRY MUSTARD.
WE HAVE A MIXTURE OF BLACK
PEPPER AND WHITE PEPPER.
OLD BAY SEASONING?
OF COURSE.
IT'S LIKE
A PREREQUISITE IN LIFE
THAT YOU USE
OLD BAY SEASONING.
IT'S A MARYLAND THING.
FRESH PARSLEY. PIMENTOS.
EGGS. AND THAT'S IT.
OPA!
(laughs)
AND VERY GENTLY WE MIX IT.
JUST ENOUGH TO HOLD IT
TOGETHER.
YES.
HOW MANY WILL THIS MAKE?
USUALLY ABOUT 65, 70.
AND THAT'S IT.
(sizzling)
OKAY, SO WE'RE READY
TO COOK ON THE GRILL.
I ONLY NEED ONE.
(laughs)
HOW MANY COME
WITH AN ORDER?
TWO.
TWO COME WITH AN ORDER?
YEAH.
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
WHO CAN EAT THAT MUCH?
I WON'T BE ABLE TO LEAVE
AFTER THIS.
(laughing)
WE'RE READY TO FLIP.
SO JUST ENOUGH TO WARM IT
THROUGH,
PUT A LITTLE CRUST,
AND THEN WE SERVE IT.
YES.
THEY READY?
YES, THEY'RE READY.
DIG IN, BUDDY.
(Guy) THIS HERE IS VERY LIGHT,
AND YOU GET BIG, FAT CHUNKS
OF CRAB ALL THROUGHOUT.
MMM! (mouth full) THAT'S
MY KIND OF CRAB CAKE.
THAT IS CRAB-A-LICIOUS.
ONLY PROBLEM I GOT--
YOU GAVE ME, LIKE,
THE WHOLE CRAB BOAT.
(laughs)
CAN ANYBODY EAT
THE WHOLE THING?
USUALLY PEOPLE
TAKE IT HOME.
IT'S DELICIOUS, MAN. MMM!
WAS THAT HOW YOUR GRANDPA
TAUGHT YOU?
WELL, IT TOOK HIM 15 YEARS
TO GIVE ME THE RECIPE
FOR THIS CRAB CAKE.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH. HE DON'T TRUST
ANYBODY.
15 YEARS WAS--
I GOT MY PRACTICE.
(mouth full) I GOTTA
TELL YOU, MAN.
COME TO BALTIMORE.
YOU WANT TO HAVE
A REAL CRAB CAKE,
YOU WANNA SEE IT DONE
THE RIGHT WAY,
YOU WANNA TASTE THE CRAB,
YOU WANNA SEE THE CRAB,
THIS IS THE PLACE TO COME.
THANK YOU, GUY.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
APPRECIATE IT.
OKAY, CRAB CAKE PLATTER.
DELICIOUS, LUMPY CRAB MEAT.
DEFINITELY THE BEST
CRAB CAKES IN TOWN.
AND WHILE PEOPLE
ARE COMING HERE FOR THE FOOD...
EVERYTHING ON THE MENU
IS GREAT.
THEY'RE ALSO HERE
FOR THE SHOW.
HOW YOU DOING TODAY, SIR?
I KEEP COMING BACK
BECAUSE OF TONY AND SOFIA.
UP NEXT...
GET YOU A NICE, BIG
PIECE, GUY.
HOLY MOLEY.
I'M HANGIN' OUT
WITH TONY'S BETTER HALF.
I'M A GREEK SPECIALIST.
HA!
AND WE MIGHT EVEN
GET TO COOK.
SMELLS LIKE GOAT CHEESE.
SERIOUSLY?!
(laughing)
I SAID "MIGHT."
I'M GONNA KILL HIM!
(laughing)
♪♪
TRIPLE "D" IS HANGIN'
AT SIP & BITE,
A BALTIMORE LANDMARK...
SOFIA, PICKUP--GREEK SALAD.
WHERE OWNERS TONY AND SOFIA
VASILIADES
ARE ROCKIN' THE GRILL...
ONE LAMB GYRO COMING UP.
PICKUP, PLEASE.
AND RUNNIN' THE FLOOR.
IT IS THE GREEK
LUCY AND RICKY SHOW.
HOW MUCH LONGER?
COMING RIGHT UP.
HOLD YOUR HORSES.
SOFIA KNOWS HER WAY
AROUND THE KITCHEN, TOO.
I'M A GREEK SPECIALIST.
HA!
'CAUSE GET THIS...
THANK YOU.
SHE ALSO GREW UP WORKING
IN HER FAMILY'S RESTAURANT.
IS THAT LEGAL? ARE YOU
ALLOWED TO TAKE THE WIFE
FROM A RESTAURANT FAMILY
AND BRING THEM OVER
AND HAVE HER WORK
AT YOUR RESTAURANT?
ONLY IF IT'S A BETTER
RESTAURANT.
OH-HO!
AND TO SWEETEN TO DEAL,
SHE BROUGHT A FAMILY SECRET
WITH HER.
SPANAKOPITA.
THANK YOU.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE ARE MAKING SOFIA'S
FAMOUS SPANAKOPITA.
WHY IS IT FAMOUS?
'CAUSE IT'S MY GRANDMOTHER'S
RECIPE.
SO--OH! OH!
SO YOU TAKE YOUR FAMILY'S
RECIPE
AND BRING IT OVER TO YOUR
HUSBAND'S FAMILY'S RESTAURANT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OH, MY GRANDMOTHER GLADLY
GAVE IT OVER TO ME.
I'M HER NAMESAKE.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
YOUR NAME'S GRANDMA?
GRAN-- (laughs)
IT STARTS WITH WHAT?
THE GREEK
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
YOU'RE SURE IT'S GREEK?
I'M SURE IT'S GREEK.
YOU'RE POSITIVE?
'CAUSE IT'S THE BEST.
IT'S GREEK.
NOW I'M GONNA ADD
MY SHALLOTS.
MIX THAT AROUND. ADD SOME
LEEKS, SOME FRESH GARLIC.
WE JUST LET THIS SWEAT OUT?
LET IT SWEAT.
SO THESE ARE SWEATED? OW!
YEAH.
I'M SORRY, I'M SORRY.
YOU SHOULDN'T WEAR--
WHAT DID YOU--
YOU'RE WEARING FLIP-FLOPS
ON THE EAST COAST!
WHAT IS THIS, CALI?
WHAT IS THIS?
IT--IT--RIGHT NOW IT IS.
WHAT DO YOU GOT--
YOU GOT YOUR MONSTER CLOGS ON?
I DO. I GOT
MY WORK SHOES ON.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
NOW TIME FOR
OUR FRESH SPINACH.
SCALLIONS, AND THEN WE DROP
THE HEAT A LITTLE BIT.
COVER IT, SWEAT 'EM OUT.
ALL RIGHT.
WHERE ARE WE AT?
BEATING UP SOME EGGS.
NOW WE HAVE SOME RICOTTA CHEESE.
I PUT THAT IN FIRST.
GONNA MIX THIS UP.
KIND OF BECOMES A PASTE.
AND THEN I'M PUTTING IN
MY KEFALOTYRI.
KA-KA-TET-A-HEE-HO?
(Sofia) IT'S GOAT CHEESE.
KEFALOTYRI.
KE... FA... LO...
LO...TYRI.
TYRI.
PERFECT.
OKAY, SO THE GOAT CHEESE
IN THERE,
THE RICOTTA CHEESE
IS IN THERE.
OKAY, WE MIX THAT.
NOW I ADD BLACK PEPPER,
FRESH MINT, NUTMEG.
OKAY.
SO YOU GRATED THE NUTMEG,
WHICH IS KEY.
YEAH.
(Sofia) AND THEN WE HAVE SOME
FRESH DILL AS WELL. MIX THAT UP.
SO THAT'S ALL MIXED IN.
SO THEN WE PUT THIS
IN THERE.
IT SMELLS LIKE GOAT CHEESE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE IT'S
KEFALOTYRI.
IT'S GOAT CHEESE.
NO, I MEAN, SERIOUSLY.
NO, YOU SMELL IT.
IT SMELLS LIKE GOAT CHEESE...
(sniffs) AND BUFALA
MOZZARELLA.
(both laughing)
I'M GONNA KILL HIM!
(laughing)
SERIOUSLY?!
(laughing continues)
I GOT HER WITH A SPATULA
FULL OF THE CHEESE!
YOU'RE GONNA GET A BALTIMORE
WHOOPING IN A SECOND!
(laughing)
SHE'S GONNA KILL ME!
SHE'S FEISTY.
I'M GONNA KICK HIM!
(laughing) AND I PUT THE SPATULA
RIGHT UNDER HER NOSE!
(laughs)
THIS MIGHT BE ONE OF
THE FUNNIEST EVER.
I SHOULD HAVE GOTTEN HIM
ONE--
OH, MY GOSH.
YOU ARE PRICELESS.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU. I KNOW
THE FOOD'S GONNA BE THE BOMB,
BUT YOU'VE JUST GOTTA MAKE
SURE YOU COME WHEN SHE'S HERE.
IT WILL CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
OKAY, SO NOW, NEXT STEP?
I'M GONNA ADD THE FETA.
JUST FOLD THAT IN
REALLY GENTLY.
SMELLS LIKE CHOCOLATE.
(laughs) GO AHEAD.
DO IT AGAIN.
GO AHEAD, TRY--REALLY.
OKAY, SO YOU STIR THIS IN.
LET IT COOL DOWN,
AND THEN
WE'LL START MAKING THEM.
YEP.
THIS IS COOL.
I MEAN, I DIG IT.
I WILL TELL YOU,
THAT'S MORE CHEESE
THAN I NORMALLY SEE
IN SPANAKOPITA.
OF COURSE.
ALL RIGHT, SO GIVE ME
A RUNDOWN.
I'M GONNA BRUSH THE PAN
WITH MY OLIVE OIL.
I'M GONNA USE
A NUMBER 10 PHYLLO.
I'M GONNA PUT IT ON THE BOTTOM
'CAUSE IT'S THICKER.
THICKER? SO YOU KNOW
YOU'RE REALLY INTO
THE SPANAKOPITA WORLD
WHEN YOU'RE CALLING OUT
YOUR GAUGE NUMBER
ON YOUR PHYLLO.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GONNA LAY THIS FLAT,
BRUSH IT VERY LIBERALLY
WITH GREEK OLIVE OIL.
REALLY? I DON'T KNOW THAT I'VE
DONE IT WITH GREEK OLIVE OIL.
OKAY.
OKAY, SO YOU GOT
SIX LAYERS IN.
YEP.
NOW?
NOW I'M GONNA PUT MY FILLING
IN, RIGHT ON TOP.
POUR IT IN? HOW MUCH?
YEP. ALL OF IT.
ALL OF IT?!
ALL OF IT.
WE'RE NOT DOING LAYERS?
NO.
HOLY MOLEY.
SO I'M GONNA TAKE
MY NUMBER 7 PHYLLO NOW
AND PUT IT ON TOP,
BRUSH EACH ONE.
SO YOU'RE TUCKING IT IN,
BRUSHING WITH THE OLIVE OIL.
TUCKING IN THE SIDES,
HOW MANY LAYERS?
I PUT AT LEAST TEN LAYERS
ON TOP.
BUT THE TOP LAYER IS SPECIAL,
'CAUSE THAT GETS AN EGG WASH.
MAKES IT NICE AND GOLDEN BROWN.
SO I'M GONNA SCORE IT.
WHY NOT ALL THE WAY THROUGH?
BECAUSE THEN IT'LL GET
REALLY MESSY.
IT'LL BE GOOD. TRUST ME.
WHY WOULDN'T I?
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
I GOT YOU.
OKAY, IN THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP?
350.
FOR HOW LONG?
ABOUT AN HOUR.
AW, IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
IS IT DONE?
IT'S LOOKING PERFECT.
YES!
(groans) OKAY! LET ME GET YOU
A NICE, BIG PIECE, GUY.
HOLY MOLEY. I DO LIKE
THE THICK--
PHYLLO NOW?
PHYLLO ON THE BOTTOM.
(mouth full) MMM! I ALWAYS
WANT MORE OF THAT TEXTURE.
AND IT'S A REALLY NICE
BLEND.
YOUR GRANDMA DID YOU RIGHT.
SHE HOOKED YOU UP.
YOU MAKE THIS FRESH
EVERY DAY?
EVERY DAY.
(mouth full) YOU DID
A ROCK STAR JOB, GIRL.
IT'S VERY LIGHT AND FLUFFY.
THE CHEESES ARE VERY GOOD.
FRESH SPINACH.
THE LAYERS ARE VERY FLAKY.
(man) HAS AN EXCELLENT
TASTE TO IT.
IT'S ALL GOOD.
DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO EAT.
COME DOWN FOR THE FOOD,
BUT PLEASE STICK AROUND
FOR THE SHOW.
GET THIS ONE GOING
OVER HERE...
(laughs)
AND I'M NOT KIDDING YOU,
YOU WON'T LEAVE.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS EDITION
OF "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
AMERICA, THIS IS BECAUSE
EVERYBODY ON TRIPLE "D"
LOVES YOU.
LET IT GET RIGHT DOWN.
THE DONNY METER.
(whispers) IT'S HOT.
BEEP, BEEP, BEEP, BEEP!
(laughter)
THAT'S HOT.
(man) YO, WATER! WATER!
(laughter)