HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
AAH!
WE'RE GETTING A LITTLE SURF...
A LITTLE HOKEY POKEY.
AND A WHOLE LOT OF TURF...
I'M GONNA ROLL
OUT OF HERE.
IN HORN LAKE, MISSISSIPPI...
THIS IS GONNA BE SWEET.
A MEMPHIS BARBECUE SHACK...
THAT'S A LITTLE ABRACADABRA
RIGHT THERE.
PUTTING THE CHAMPIONSHIP TOUCH
ON BURGERS...
SMASH.
RIBS...
I'M GONNA NEED, LIKE,
A BEACH TOWEL.
EVEN CHEESE...
WHOA.
AND IN KANEOHE, OAHU...
OKAY, POKE.
THE POKE PLACE...
YOU GOT TO GET ONE OF THESE,
LIKE...
LIKE A TIGER.
CUBING UP THE FRESH FISH...
LOOK AT THAT.
AND GOING OVERBOARD
TO FIND THE FLAVOR.
LOOK, SOMEONE'S PULLING UP.
I WONDER WHO IT IS, HONEY?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE “D.”
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW, ON TRIPLE “D”
WE HAVE SHOT
SO MANY BARBECUE RESTAURANTS,
BUT I GOT TO TELL YOU,
THE ONES I REALLY, REALLY DIG
IS WHERE THE OWNERS COMPETE
IN BARBECUE COMPETITIONS.
THESE FOLKS HERE,
WELL, THEY HAVEN'T JUST COMPETED
IN THE COMPETITION.
THEY'VE BEEN KICKING BUTT
AND TAKING NAMES
IN SOME OF THE BIGGEST.
SO I'M ABOUT 15 MILES OUTSIDE
OF DOWNTOWN MEMPHIS,
BUT I'M IN MISSISSIPPI
TO CHECK OUT
MEMPHIS BARBECUE COMPANY.
THEY HAVE
THE MOST AWESOME BURGERS.
THE BRISKET'S SO MOIST.
(woman) THE PULLED PORK
IS THE BEST.
ONE OF THE FEW RESTAURANTS
THAT I CAN SAY
THAT YOU WILL GET
WORLD CHAMPIONSHIP BARBECUE.
THAT'S 'CAUSE THE FACTS
DON'T LIE.
SPARE RIBS DRY. CAN I GET
SOME CHEESE FRITTERS, PLEASE?
PIT MASTER
MELISSA COOKSTON'S TEAM
HAS COME UP HUGE
AT MEMPHIS IN MAY,
ONE OF THE LARGEST BARBECUE
COMPETITIONS ON THE PLANET.
(Guy) YOU WIN 2010, 2011,
AND YOU JUST WON 2012?
THAT'S AMAZING.
AND WITH HUSBAND PETE
AND FELLOW CHAMP JOHN WHEELER
BY HER SIDE,
EVERY DAY IS A WINNER
FOR THE CUSTOMER.
BABY BACK RIBS.
(woman) YOU CAN SAY
YOU'VE GOTTEN CHAMPIONSHIP RIBS
WHEN YOU SIT DOWN HERE.
IT'S FINGER-LICKING.
EACH RACK SMOTHERED IN THE RUB
THAT'S HELPED HER
BRING HOME THE GOLD.
(Melissa)
THIS IS OUR RUB,
AND THIS IS THE MOST USED
INGREDIENT IN THIS RESTAURANT.
AND YOU'RE GONNA SHARE
THE RECIPE WITH US?
WITH YOU.
WITH ME. OH, YEAH, 'CAUSE DON'T
WORRY, NO TAPE IN THE CAMERAS.
EXACTLY.
AND I KNOW
THE CAST OF CHARACTERS HERE.
VERY SIMPLE, VERY BASIC.
AND VERY SWEET.
MEMPHIS-STYLE FLAVOR PROFILE
IS VERY SULTRY
WITH JUST A LITTLE SWEET
AND A LITTLE KICK IN THE BACK.
SO LET'S MAKE THIS.
THIS IS A FINE-GROUND
TURBINADO SUGAR.
IF YOU GO TO A COFFEE SHOP
AND YOU SEE WHERE IT SAYS
SUGAR IN THE RAW
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT,
THAT'S TURBINADO SUGAR.
TURBINADO HAS A HIGHER
CARAMELIZATION POINT
AS OPPOSED TO WHITE
OR BROWN SUGAR.
CHILI POWDER.
KOSHER SALT.
THIS IS OUR PAPRIKA.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
LITTLE MUSTARD.
DRIED MUSTARD.
CUMIN.
THAT'S IT
FOR THE BLACK PEPPER?
THAT'S IT.
(whistles)
A LITTLE CAYENNE.
SOME ONION.
AND ONION POWDER.
I GO THROUGH
400 POUNDS A WEEK.
NO.
WE'RE GONNA PUT THIS
ON OUR RIBS,
AND THIS IS A BASE FLAVORING
FOR OUR SAUCE.
THIS IS THE SEASONING
FOR EVERYTHING BUT BURGERS.
YOU'RE GONNA PUT IT
ON A FLIP-FLOP?
NO, I DON'T
EAT FLIP-FLOPS.
REALLY? YOU SHOULD TRY 'EM.
IT'S A NEW PROTEIN.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE GOT THIS DONE.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME SAUCE.
THIS IS MY BABY.
(laughs)
STEAM KETTLE.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA START
OFF WITH SOME KETCHUP,
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
(laughs)
YEAH, REALLY I LIKE THE WAY
YOU'RE REALLY DIALING IT BACK.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA PUT
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN IT COME OUT
OF AN OIL TANKER.
THEN WE'RE GONNA PUT
LIGHT CORN SYRUP, YEAH.
A LITTLE CORN SYRUP.
THIS IS GONNA BE SWEET.
WATER.
WHITE DISTILLED VINEGAR.
THAT'LL CUT A LITTLE BIT
OF THE SWEETNESS.
YEAH, IT'LL CUT
A LITTLE BIT OF YOUR SWEETNESS.
WOW. HONEY.
YELLOW MUSTARD.
HOW MANY GALLONS OF THIS
WILL YOU MAKE A WEEK?
50 TO 75 GALLONS A DAY,
DEPENDING ON WHETHER IT'S DURING
THE WEEK OR ON THE WEEKEND.
THEN WE HAVE TOMATO PASTE.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
GARLIC SALT.
KOSHER SALT.
BLACK PEPPER.
CAYENNE PEPPER.
OUR ULTIMATE RUB.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
BROWN SUGAR.
OH. LOOK AT THAT.
(laughs)
IS YOUR DAD A LOCAL DENTIST
OR SOMETHING?
OH, YEAH.
IT TAKES A STIR
FOR ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
SO YOU MIX IT UP.
THEN YOU TURN IT ON,
180 DEGREES, 2 HOURS,
GET IT IN THE COOLER.
YEP.
GOT IT.
NOW LET'S PREP
OUR BABY BACK RIBS.
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
FIRST THING YOU WANT TO DO IS
TAKE OFF THIS BLASTED MEMBRANE.
(zipping, whipping)
THAT'S A LITTLE ABRACADABRA
RIGHT THERE.
(laughs) ALL RIGHT, THEN
WE WANT TO SEASON BOTH SIDES.
THE MUSTARD ACTS AS A SEALANT.
RUB THIS IN.
NOW THEY GO IN THE WALK-IN.
OKAY.
WE LEAVE 'EM
IN THERE OVERNIGHT.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD
ARE WE GONNA SMOKE 'EM WITH?
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE
WITH PECAN.
I'M GONNA RUN THESE
AT 220 FOR THE FIRST 2 HOURS...
OKAY.
AND THEN I'LL BUMP IT UP
TO 230.
OKAY. FOR HOW LONG?
FIVE HOURS TOTAL.
ALL RIGHT, GOT THESE
OFF THE SMOKER.
SAUCE ONE SIDE,
DRY RUB THE OTHER SIDE...
I DIG IT.
'CAUSE I'M GONNA LET YOU PICK
WHAT YOU LIKE BEST.
THAT DRY RUB IS CRAZY...
I KNOW.
WITH THE BALANCE OF THE SUGAR
TO THE SALT,
BUT IT'S NOT OVERLY SWEET.
SEE HOW THE MEAT
COMES OFF THERE,
BUT EVERYTHING
DOESN'T COME OFF.
WHEN YOU SAY
THAT YOU DO 'EM WET,
THAT'S NOT SLOPPY WET.
NO.
I LIKE WHEN THAT SAUCE
IS TIGHT TO IT.
SO THE RIB WAS STILL HOT ENOUGH
THAT IT MELTED IN.
HUH? IS THERE SOME
RIGHT HERE?
I NEED, LIKE,
A BEACH TOWEL.
IT'S NOT GOOD BARBECUE
IF YOU DON'T HAVE IT ALL...
IF IT'S NOT
IN YOUR EARLOBE? YEAH.
YES.
IS IT GOOD?
(clicks tongue) ALL RIGHT.
(laughs)
(man) LIVING IN MEMPHIS,
WE EAT RIBS FREQUENTLY,
AND I'D RANK THESE UP THERE
WITH THE BEST.
THEY'RE MOIST. THEY'RE MEATY.
THEY'VE GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
WET OR DRY, THEY'RE BONA FIDE.
(man) OUT OF THE HUNDRED OR SO
BARBECUE PLACES
THAT ARE AROUND HERE,
THIS IS MY TOP BARBECUE PLACE.
BUT IT TAKES MORE
THAN JUST MELISSA
TO SERVE UP
THESE GREAT FLAVORS.
EVEN HER DAUGHTER LAUREN
IS STEPPING UP TO THE PLATE.
SHE'S 13.
YEARS OLD.
YES. AND SHE IS
MY HEAD HOSTESS.
THIS IS A MOM
BEING A LITTLE MODEST NOW.
SHE IS THE 5-TIME MISSISSIPPI
STATE HAMBURGER CHAMPION.
SHE COMPETED IN HER FIRST
COMPETITION WHEN SHE WAS 6.
SERIOUSLY.
WITH WHAT RECIPE?
WITH HER OWN RECIPE.
THAT EVOLVED INTO ONE
OF THIS JOINT'S TOP SELLERS.
CRUNCH BURGER.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
LIKE IT BEFORE.
SO WHAT MAKES IT CRUNCH?
PORK RINDS.
I KNOW PORK RINDS. CHICHARRONES
WE HAVE IN CALIFORNIA.
THIS IS WHAT
IT'S COMING FROM?
THEY'RE SMOKED
DEHYDRATED PORK FAT
THAT WE'RE GONNA FRY IT.
NO.
NOT SO MUCH CRUNCH.
NOT YET.
LET'S FRY 'EM.
LET'S GO.
FRY'S UP.
SO THIS IS IT.
A LITTLE BARBECUE RUB ON THERE.
MMM.
AND THEN THESE
WILL ACTUALLY GO ON THE BURGER?
THEY ACTUALLY GO ON TOP
OF THE BURGER.
YOU BETTER HURRY UP AND MAKE 'EM
BEFORE I EAT 'EM ALL.
ALL RIGHT.
ONE BURGER
OR TWO BURGERS?
WELL, YOU GET
TWO BURGER PATTIES.
I'M GONNA ROLL
OUT OF HERE.
SMASH 'EM OUT.
NICE TECHNIQUE.
A LITTLE
HAMBURGER SEASONING-
THIS IS MINCED ONION,
GARLIC,
SEASONED SALT,
LITTLE BLACK PEPPER.
THIS IS OUR SPICY
BARBECUE SAUCE.
OKAY.
PUT A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
ON THE BURGER PATTY.
SAME BASIS OF HOW YOU START
YOUR OTHER BARBECUE SAUCE?
IT IS EXACTLY THE SAME.
FOLLOWED BY
SOME CHEDDAR CHEESE.
NOW WE HAVE TO DO
SECRET STUFF.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT,
BURGER'S READY.
JUKE SAUCE.
WHO?
IT COMES FROM DOWN
IN MISSISSIPPI, JUKE JOINTS.
CHEESY GOODNESS.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
THE PORK RINDS.
THAT'S A CRUNCH BURGER.
I LIKE IT.
SMASH. (laughs)
THAT CHICHARRóN IN THERE.
MMM. THE JUKE SAUCE
IS GREAT, TOO. MMM.
THE BURGER'S COOKED PERFECTLY,
NICE MELT ON THE CHEESE.
YOU GOT ALL THE PRODUCE
YOU NEED IN THERE,
BUT IT'S WHEN YOU GET
THAT EXTRA LITTLE CRUNCH
OUT OF THAT CHICHARRóN--MMM.
DYNAMITE BURGER.
THANK YOU.
COOKED RIGHT, SEASONED RIGHT,
ENOUGH INGREDIENTS,
RIDICULOUSLY TOO BIG.
AND THE CHICHARRóN
MADE IT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU MUCH.
WORLD CHAMPION.
IT'S A FISTFUL OF HAMBURGER,
JUST SO MANY DIFFERENT FLAVORS.
THIS IS REALLY KILLER.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE HANGING
OUT AT MEMPHIS BARBECUE COMPANY.
WHAT DO YOU GOT NEXT?
IT'S A CHEESE STICK
FOR ADULTS.
NO, IT'S AN ADVERTISEMENT
FOR A GYM.
(woman) CHEESE FRITTERS.
THAT'S CRAZY.
SEE YOU IN A BIT.
AT MEMPHIS BARBECUE COMPANY
IN HORN LAKE, MISSISSIPPI,
PIT MASTER MELISSA COOKSTON'S
GOT THE CHAMPIONSHIP TOUCH
WHEN IT COMES TO SMOKING...
(Melissa) BRISKETS, SPARE RIBS,
LOIN BACK RIBS,
CHICKEN, STEAKS, BURGERS.
BUT FOR THIS
DEEP-FRIED APPETIZER...
CHEESE FRITTERS.
YUM.
SHE'S PUTTING DOWN THE MEAT
FOR 13 1/2 POUNDS
OF CREAMY GOODNESS.
4 1/2, 4, 3, AND 2.
SERIOUSLY?
IT'S ABOUT THE CHEESE.
I LOVE CHEESE.
ALL RIGHT,
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH SOME SOUR CREAM.
WHOSE RECIPE?
THIS IS A RECIPE
THAT MY HUSBAND AND I
ACTUALLY DEVELOPED TOGETHER.
MOST COUPLES, YOU KNOW,
THEY GO ON TRIPS
OR HORSEBACK RIDING
OR CAMPING.
NO, WE PLAY WITH FOOD.
MINCED GARLIC.
GREEN ONIONS.
GARLIC SALT.
NICE.
YES. KOSHER SALT.
PARSLEY FLAKES.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF CAYENNE
FOR A LITTLE KICK.
AND A WHOLE LOT
OF BEATEN EGGS.
MMM.
CAN I LICK THE BOWL?
ADD FLOUR.
JUST ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR?
THIS IS ACTUALLY
SELF-RISING FLOUR...
(whistles)
BECAUSE WE WANT TO BE ABLE
FOR THE CHEESE BALLS
TO PUFF UP A LITTLE BIT,
YEP.
GOT IT.
I'M GONNA NEED YOUR HELP
IN A MINUTE.
OH, ABSOLUTELY.
MY HANDS ARE GONNA BE NASTY,
SO...
YOU WANT ME TO GET A FOOT IN
THERE OR WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
YEAH, YOU COULD JUST START
POURING SOME OF THE CHEESE IN.
MOZZARELLA.
I DIDN'T REALLY PUT
CHEESE SPRINKLER ON MY RéSUMé,
BUT NOW THAT I'M THINKING
ABOUT IT...
(laughs) SWISS.
YOU'RE DOING A GREAT JOB.
AWESOME.
PARMESAN.
THAT IS THE MOST CHEESE I'VE
EVER SEEN IN A CHEESE FRITTER.
CHEDDAR.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
THIS IS WHERE YOU REALLY START
TO GET YOUR WORKOUT.
YES, MAKES FOR
NICE, BIG MUSCLES.
(normal voice) OKAY, SO WE TAKE
'EM, ROLL 'EM INTO THE BALL.
WHAT SIZE BALL
ARE YOU GONNA MAKE 'EM INTO?
(whipping, bell dings)
OH.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
PUT 'EM IN OIL, 350 DEGREES.
INTO WHAT?
OIL.
NO, YOU DIDN'T SAY IT
THAT WAY BEFORE.
I LOVE IT. THAT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITE SOUTHERN WORDS.
(southern accent) OIL.
OIL.
HOW LONG ARE THESE
GONNA GO DOWN FOR?
TWO MINUTES.
OKAY.
WOW.
THESE ARE GOLDEN.
THIS IS
THE HONEY DIJON--
A MIXTURE OF HONEY...
DIJON.
DIJON MUSTARD,
SPICY MUSTARD, SUGAR,
YOU KNOW,
OOEY GOOEY GOODNESS.
AND THEN, VOILà.
MMM. THAT'S NUTS.
THE CHEESE I REALLY LIKE
OUT OF THAT, RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
IS THAT SWISS.
IT HOLDS TOGETHER.
NOT OVERLY SALTY,
NOT OVERLY ONE FLAVOR.
I DO GET THAT GARLIC.
I DO GET THAT SWISS.
NICE SORT OF CRUNCHY TEXTURE
ON THE OUTSIDE.
THIS HONEY DIJON MOAT THAT
IT'S IN DOES PERFECT FOR IT.
THAT'S CRAZY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE BITE
TO IT.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE A HUSH PUPPY
STUFFED WITH CREAM CHEESE.
IT'S MORE THAN JUST
YOUR AVERAGE CHEESE STICK.
CHEESE FRITTERS.
(man) HOT RIBS
COMING OVER.
ALL RIGHT, SPARE RIBS DRY,
BABY BACK WET.
(man)
WHEN WE JUDGE BARBECUE,
WE START WITH 10
AND WORK OUR WAY DOWN,
AND I THINK THIS
WOULD GET MY 10.
WELL, I DROVE
ABOUT 50 MILES TODAY.
I PROBABLY WOULD DRIVE 100.
(man) WHEN I HAVE
OUT-OF-TOWN GUESTS COME IN,
WE TRY TO HIT THREE PLACES--
GRACELAND, THE MEMPHIS ZOO,
AND I BRING 'EM
TO THE MEMPHIS BARBECUE COMPANY.
THE FINEST BARBECUE
IN THE MID-SOUTH AREA.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT?
YOU GOT A COP AND A GUY
THAT'S WITH A COP.
THEY DON'T LIE.
(laughs)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO KANEOHE, OAHU...
AHH!
FOR FISH SO LEGIT...
I COULD SIT HERE
AND EAT THIS BY THE BUCKETFUL.
IT MAKES YOU WANT TO DANCE.
A LITTLE HOKEY TO THE RIGHT,
A LITTLE HOKEY TO THE LEFT.
A LITTLE HOKEY POKEY.
YOU KNOW,
IN THE MOVIE “FORREST GUMP”
WHEN BUBBA TALKS ABOUT SHRIMP
AND ALL THE WAYS
YOU CAN HAVE IT?
THAT'S KIND OF HOW I FEEL
ABOUT POKE.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE CUT-UP FISH
THAT'S SEASONED
SO MANY DIFFERENT WAYS.
I MEAN, YOU COULD HAVE
TAKO POKE--THAT'S OCTOPUS--
AHI POKE, SHRIMP POKE.
I MEAN, THE LIST
JUST GOES ON AND ON.
AND IT'S NOT JUST
ABOUT THE VARIATIONS.
IT'S ABOUT THE FRESHNESS.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE AT KANEOHE.
ABOUT 11 MILES FROM HONOLULU,
THIS IS FRESH CATCH.
(man) FIRE BOWL AHI.
SPICY SALMON.
I DRIVE ALL THE WAY FROM
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE ISLAND
JUST TO COME HERE.
HE EATS HERE
ABOUT SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
WE'VE GOT AN AHI KATSU.
THIS IS DOM RAIOLA
WHO PLAYS FOR THE DETROIT LIONS.
OVER PREMIUM STEAK HOUSES ACROSS
THE COUNTRY, THIS IS YOUR GO-TO.
OH, YEAH. THIS IS WHAT
I WAS RAISED ON.
IT'S PURELY HAWAIIAN.
AS HAWAIIAN
AS RENO HENRIQUES...
ONE SMOKING HAWAIIAN PLATE.
AN EAST SIDE NATIVE
WHOSE LOVE FOR THE POKE
TRUMPED THE FAMILY BUSINESS.
PROBABLY THE BIGGEST
RUBBISH COMPANY IN HAWAII.
RUBBISH?
THEY PICK UP RUBBISH.
TRASH.
YEAH, TRASH MAN.
TRADING RUBBISH FOR FRESH FISH?
NOT A BAD DEAL.
I LOVE
TO MAKE PEOPLE HAPPY,
WATCH THE SMILE ON EVERYBODY'S
FACES WHILE THEY EAT MY FOOD.
THERE'S SMILES ALL AROUND
FOR THE 30 DIFFERENT POKES
COMING OUT OF THE KITCHEN,
INCLUDING ONE...
SOME AHI LIMU.
MADE WITH A FISH SO BIG IT'S
GOTTA HAVE ITS OWN THEME MUSIC.
(hums)
AAH!
HOLY TUNA.
THIS IS A BIG AHI TUNA.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
SO WHAT I'M GONNA DO...
PECTORAL FIN OVER.
I'M JUST GONNA CUT IT
RIGHT THERE.
AND GIVE IT ONE HIYA.
AHH!
(whistles)
HEY, IT'S A HAT. (laughs)
THEN WE TAKE THE KNIFE
RIGHT DOWN THE CENTER.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE YOU GO. THAT'S
YOUR BASIC AHI FILLET.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA
DO WITH THIS?
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT UP
AND MAKE SOME POKE WITH IT--
AHI LIMU POKE.
WHAT DOES POKE
TRANSLATE?
POKE JUST IS CUT UP--
SMALL CUTS.
SMALL CUTS?
YEP.
OKAY, SO NOW WE GOT IT
CHOPPED UP.
WHAT IS THIS FREAKY
LITTLE THING?
THAT'S OUR KUKUI NUT.
WHAT NUT?
KUKUI NUT.
KUKUI NUT IS OUT, UH,
HAWAII STATE TREE.
AFTER YOU ROAST IT,
IT KINDA LOOKS LIKE THIS,
A LITTLE BURNT
ON THE OUTSIDE...
OKAY.
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE JUST GONNA--
YOU JUST PUT A RAG OVER IT,
OUR BACK OF OUR CLEAVER,
KIND OF SMASH IT UP,
AND THEN YOU JUST, UM,
DIG OUT ALL THE MEAT
INSIDE OF IT.
THAT'S YOUR KUKUI NUT.
YOU DON'T EAT TOO--
TOO MUCH OF IT.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE
A HAWAIIAN LAXATIVE.
NOW I TELL YOU.
AWESOME.
GIVE IT A LITTLE
ROUGH CHOP FIRST.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT
THE CRAZY NUT.
ALL RIGHT,
WE GOT OUR CRAZY NUT,
SO NOW WE GOT OUR
AHI CUBES IN A BOWL,
WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT
WITH SOME HAWAIIAN SEA SALT.
OKAY.
THEN WE GOT OUR KUKUI NUT,
SOME HAWAIIAN CHILI FLAKES.
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD TO PUT
YOUR DRY INGREDIENTS FIRST
WHILE YOU MIX IT,
'CAUSE IF YOU START PUTTING
YOUR WET INGREDIENTS,
EVERYTHING WILL GET STUCK.
SO WE'RE GONNA GIVE IT A COUPLE
GOOD MIXES UP OVER HERE.
YOU DON'T REALLY
WANT TO OVERMIX IT.
DON'T WANT TO BREAK
THE FISH UP.
NOPE. GOT OUR HAWAIIAN
CHILI PEPPER WATER.
OKAY.
IT'S JUST HAWAIIAN
CHILI PEPPERS,
SOME HAWAIIAN SALT,
AND WATER.
SESAME OIL,
A COUPLE MIXES, GREEN ONION.
WE GOT SOME WHITE ONION.
OUR LIMU, OR SEAWEED,
SO LET'S GIVE IT A FINE CHOP,
PUT IT IN OUR MIXING BOWL,
GIVE IT A COUPLE
GOOD MIXES AGAIN,
AND THERE WE GO. WE GOT
OUR BASIC AHI LIMU RIGHT THERE.
I COULD SIT HERE AND EAT THIS
BY THE BUCKETFUL.
IT'S TENDER, IT'S FRESH.
ALL THE INGREDIENTS
GO TOGETHER WELL.
SO BALANCED AND SO DELICATE,
SO FLAVORFUL.
I MEAN, YOU JUST GET
THE REAL DEAL IN THIS, MAN.
I'VE HAD A LOT OF POKE ON THIS
ISLAND AS WELL. THAT'S LEGIT.
SOME AHI LIMU.
HAVE YOU HAD IT
OTHER PLACES?
YEAH, BUT I ALWAYS COME
TO RENO'S, ALWAYS.
REGULAR SMOKED TAKO.
WHAT MAKES GREAT
HAWAIIAN FOOD?
I THINK THE FRESHNESS.
AND IF YOU WANT IT REALLY--
AND I MEAN, REALLY FRESH,
SOMETIMES YOU GOTTA
DO THE JOB YOURSELF.
(Reno) WE GO DIVING,
CATCH OUR OWN OCTOPUS.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
YOU CATCH YOUR OWN
OCTOPUS?
STRAIGHT OUT OF THE OCEAN...
THAT'S THAT NEW HAIRDO
I WAS LOOKING FOR.
AND RIGHT INTO THE KITCHEN.
ROCK STAR.
AT FRESH CATCH
IN KANEOHE, OAHU,
THE DUDE WITH THE CHICKEN
FEATHER HEADBAND,
RENO HENRIQUES,
IS SERVING UP
OVER 30 STYLES
OF FRESH POKE EVERY DAY.
THE SECRET--
LOCATION, LOCATION, LOCATION.
WE'RE FORTUNATE IN HAWAII--
THE OCEAN IS IN OUR BACKYARD.
MOST PEOPLE AIN'T GOT
THAT OPPORTUNITY.
SO HE'S HUGE ON SUPPORTING
LOCAL FISHERMEN.
HE GOES TO THE MARKET
REALLY EARLY EVERY MORNING.
BUT HE'S NOT AFRAID
TO GO GET IT HIMSELF.
WE GO DIVING,
CATCH OUR OWN OCTOPUS,
FISHING--
(whistles)
YOU CATCH YOUR OWN OCTOPUS?
YEAH, WE CATCH OUR
OWN OCTOPUS.
THE SQUID WILL KIND OF BE
IN THE HOLE HIDING,
WITH HIS LITTLE
HAND OVER THERE.
HOW WAS THAT?
YOU GOTTA DO ONE OF THESE,
LIKE--
LIKE...
STRAIGHT FROM THE OCEAN
AND INTO THE KITCHEN
FOR THIS ISLAND FAVORITE.
SPICY TAKO.
IT'S A SMOKED OCTOPUS.
OKAY, POKE.
ONE OF OUR MOST
POPULAR POKES
IS A SPICY SMOKE TAKO.
TAKO--T-A-K-O.
OR--
T-A-K-O, TAKO.
OCTOPUS--IN HAWAII,
WE CALL IT HE 'E.
I'M GONNA HIT YOU
IN THE HE 'E.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
SO THAT'S PROBABLY ABOUT
A 4- TO 5-POUNDER RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THAT NEW HAIRDO I WAS
LOOKING FOR. SQUID LOCKS.
SO WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO CLEAN ON IT?
FIRST OF ALL,
JUST GONNA CUT THE HEAD.
SO WE GOT THE BEAK
RIGHT THERE,
SO WE'RE JUST GONNA
CUT HIS BEAK.
OKAY.
SO THE NEXT THING
WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE NEED TO PUT
OCTOPUS IN THE BOWL,
AND WE NEED TO, UH,
PUT THE HAWAIIAN SALT ON TOP,
THEN AGAIN, WE'RE GONNA USE
THE SALT TO TENDERIZE THE SQUID
AND, UH, TAKE OFF
THE SLIME.
DUDE, YOU'RE REALLY
WORKING THIS THING OUT.
SO NOW WE'LL JUST PUT IT
IN THIS BOWL.
I'VE COOKED A LOT OF SQUID, AND
I'VE SEEN A LOT OF SQUID COOKED,
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THIS PROCESS.
YOU NEED TO--
THIS IS THE BEST WAY, 'CAUSE
IT'LL COME THE MOST TENDER.
OKAY.
OKAY, MY MAN,
SO NOW WE'RE JUST
GONNA CUT IT UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
STRING 'EM RIGHT THROUGH.
JUST GONNA HANG 'EM
LIKE THAT, REALLY?
YEAH.
WHERE ARE WE GOING
WITH THIS ROD OF FUN?
RIGHT INTO MY SMOKER.
LOOK, SOMEONE'S PULLING UP.
I WONDER WHO IT IS, HONEY?
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
GO TO THE SMOKER?
YEP, TAKE IT OUT
TO THE SMOKER.
WE'RE WALKING
OUR OCTOPUS.
THIS IS THE DIABLO 5000.
COME HERE. WE HAVE GOT
SOME ALUMINUM SIDING.
I THINK HE CUT THE HOLE
IN HERE WITH A HATCHET.
WHAT WAS THIS?
THIS ACTUALLY
WAS A CABINET.
IT WAS A CABINET,
WASN'T IT?
YEAH, IT WAS A CABINET.
IN HAWAII, THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
THIS IS OLD-SCHOOL STYLE.
AS HE EXPLAINS IT TO ME,
HE WALKS AROUND
WITH THE OCTOPUS,
AND KEEPS SMACKING ME
IN THE LEGS WITH IT.
OH, LIKE THAT.
LET'S SMOKE SOME OCTOPUS.
WHAT KIND OF WOOD?
KIAWE WOOD.
A HARDWOOD, SO EITHER USE--
KIAWE OR GUAVA WOOD IN HAWAII.
AND HOW LONG ARE WE
GONNA SMOKE THIS?
FOUR HOURS.
DON'T ASK ME
WHAT TEMPERATURE IT IS.
WHEN THE PAINT STARTS
TO PEEL OFF A LITTLE BIT,
IT'S JUST ABOUT READY.
ALL RIGHT.
SMOKED OCTOPUS.
IT'S OCTOPUS JERKY.
MMM. TASTY.
LET'S GO.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
TAKE OUR SQUID OFF.
OKAY.
CUT IT UP THIN.
NICE AND TENDER.
ALMOST BUTTERY.
OKAY, SO NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR SAUCE FOR OUR SMOKED TAKO.
IN HAWAII, WE USE A LOT
OF MAYONNAISE ON THAT.
NO! THAT'S LIKE
A HOT TUB OF MAYONNAISE.
WASABI.
AND THEN WE HAVE
OUR KIMCHI PASTE.
MM-HMM.
THESE ARE MY HOMEGROWN CHILI
PEPPERS FROM AT MY HOUSE.
THEY HOT?
THEY'RE HOT, MAN.
WHISK 'EM UP. ALL RIGHT,
BUD, GIVE IT A TASTE.
ROCK STAR.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT
OUR CUT OCTOPUS.
DUMP IT IN A BOWL. WE GOT
OUR SPICY SAUCE RIGHT HERE.
GIVE IT A COUPLE
GOOD MIXES.
NOW PEOPLE COME IN
AND BUY THIS TO GO,
EAT IT HERE?
WELL, WE MAKE POKE BOWLS.
TWO SCOOPS RICE,
AND, LIKE, A HOAGIE TRAY,
WHATEVER POKE ON--
HOAGIE TRAY--SO THIS
IS LIKE HOAGIE POKE?
YEAH, HOAGIE POKE.
THERE YOU DO--
A LITTLE HOAGIE TO THE RIGHT,
AD LITTLE HOAGIE TO THE LEFT.
A LITTLE HOAGIE POKE!
SO WE GOT OUR SMOKED TAKO
IN HERE,
GARNISH IT WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF GREEN ONIONS,
AND THEN TOBIKO--
FISH EGGS.
THERE YOU GO, MY MAN.
GOOD TO GO.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
GOT GREAT TEXTURE.
THE OCTOPUS IS TENDER,
A LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE.
GOOD HEAT IN THE MAYONNAISE.
THE TOBIKO ON THERE IS NICE,
THE FRESH GREEN ONION.
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
TAKO POKE.
THIS IS JUST
DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN TASTE THE MESQUITE,
OR THE KIAWE WOOD,
AS WE CALL IT OUT HERE.
IT HAS A NICE LITTLE FLAVOR
TO IT THAT MAKES IT STAND OUT.
I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT RENO DOES,
BUT IT'S GOOD STUFF.
IT'S PERFECT.
DUDE, I'M TELLING YOU,
THIS IS LIKE
POKE PARADISE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MY MAN.
GUY'S THE BOMB.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(high-pitched voice) THAT'S ALL
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES," THE POKE PALACE.