HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
YES!
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LET'S JUST GO
TO A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
NOW WE TURN IT UP...
OW! THAT'S HOT.
WITH A FRESH TAKE
ON THE CLASSICS.
THIS WILL BE INTERESTING.
IN CHICAGO, ILLINOIS...
DUDE, YOU HAVE GOT
SOME TECHNIQUE HERE.
THE KOREAN BURGER JOINT...
SO THIS IS LIKE UMAMI
TO THE FIFTH POWER.
HITTING ON ALL CYLINDERS...
KOREAN
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
WITH A SPIN
ON AMERICAN STANDARDS.
IT IS IN THE TOP BEST BURGERS
I'VE EVER HAD.
AND IN THE TOWN
OF WAIMANALO, OAHU...
(whistles)
THE RESTORED GAS STATION
FILLING UP
ON GANGSTER TOFU BURGERS...
I SIGNED THE PETITION.
I'M ON THE TEAM.
AND TAKING
BACKYARD BARBECUE...
YOU SEE, THIS IS IT.
TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT.
LIFE IS GOOD.
LIFE IS REAL GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
RIGHT NOW
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
♪♪
ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S TALK ABOUT
SOME OF THE FANTASTIC BURGER
JOINTS WE'VE HAD ON TRIPLE “D.”
I MEAN, THE LIST
IS LONG AND DISTINGUISHED.
I MEAN, JUST TO NAME A FEW--
HODAD'S, TWISTED ROOT, THE NOOK.
I MEAN, AND THEY ALL GOT
THEIR OWN WAY THEY DO THINGS,
THEIR OWN LITTLE UNIQUE TWIST.
SO HERE I AM IN CHICAGO
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE THEY'RE PUTTING
A LITTLE ASIAN SPIN
ON SOME ALL-AMERICAN CLASSICS.
THIS IS bopNgrill.
(man) KIMCHI BURGER.
THE FOOD
IS JUST SO GOOD.
THIS IS
KOREAN MEETS AMERICAN.
THIS FROM A BURGER JOINT?
NUMBER TWO--BI BIM BOP.
SOMETHING THAT I JUST GREW UP
EATING AT HOME ALL THE TIME.
SO DID CHEF WILL SONG...
A MASTER OF BOTH AMERICAN
CUISINES AND KOREAN CUISINES.
WHO GREW UP IN THE MIDWEST
ON HIS FAMILY'S HOME COOKING.
MY MOM, ACTUALLY, TAUGHT ME
MORE OF THE KOREAN SIDE OF IT.
THE REST CAME FROM CULINARY
SCHOOL AND LOCAL KITCHENS,
AND THEN IN '09
HE OPENED UP bopNgrill.
BOP IN KOREAN
MEANS “RICE.”
I WANTED TO KIND OF
DO SOMETHING WITH RICE
AND THEN SOMETHING
KIND OF AMERICAN.
WITH AN ASIAN ATTITUDE.
WILL'S FOOD
IS FULL OF UMAMI.
A FUNKY WORD
DESCRIBING A TASTE
THAT GOES BEYOND SALT, SWEET,
SOUR, AND BITTER.
UMAMI BEING
THE FIFTH TASTE.
WHEN YOU HIT THE MOMENT
OF UMAMI, YOU ARE THERE.
HOPEFULLY, YEAH.
AND WHEN IT HAPPENS ON
A BURGER, YOU KNOW I'M THERE.
(woman) HERE'S YOUR UMAMI BURGER
AND KIMCHI FRIES.
(woman) WHEN YOU TASTE IT,
IT'S A HUGE SURPRISE TO YOU.
IT'S GOT GREAT BURSTS
OF FLAVORS.
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ARE
WE GONNA MAKE, BROTHER?
TRUFFLE DUXELLE
FOR THE UMAMI BURGER.
IT'S
A BRAISED MUSHROOM DISH.
WE'RE GONNA START OFF
WITH PORK FAT.
A LOT OF PORK FAT
IN KOREAN COOKING?
NO, JUST, I THINK,
IN MY COOKING.
BUTTER.
ONIONS.
JUST SWEAT THIS OUT,
GET IT KIND OF TRANSLUCENT.
SALT AND PEPPER.
GARLIC.
DUDE.
WE'RE JUST COOKING THE GARLIC
UNTIL IT GETS COOKED THROUGH.
SO THIS IS LIKE UMAMI
TO THE FIFTH POWER.
ONCE YOU TASTE IT,
WE'LL SEE.
I DON'T EVEN NEED BURGER
WITH THIS.
I COULD HAVE
THE DUXELLE...
WITH SOME RICE.
YEAH.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE BONITO FLAKES.
DRIED FISH FLAKES,
SOMETHING, OF COURSE,
YOU'D EXPECT TO FIND
IN A BURGER JOINT,
OH, YEAH.
IT GIVES A LITTLE BIT
OF SMOKINESS.
OF COURSE, IT DOES.
ANCHOVY DASHI.
(whistles) RICH.
MINCED
PORTOBELLO MUSHROOMS.
WOW.
SALT AND PEPPER.
WE LET THIS COOK DOWN
15, 20 MINUTES,
DRIZZLE IT
WITH SOME TRUFFLE OIL.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT,
RIGHT THERE.
DUDE, THAT'S A LOT OF TIME
AND ENERGY
FOR ONE OF THE BURGERS.
A LITTLE OIL,
80-20 ANGUS,
AND SALT AND PEPPER.
YOU'RE NOT SHORT
ON THE SEASONING,
I'LL TELL YOU THAT MUCH.
NO. NOW FLIP.
GOT TO GO FOR THE SMASH,
LITTLE SEASON AGAIN...
YEAH. RIGHT.
BUILDING CRUST.
RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA BUTTER
OUR BRIOCHE BUN.
NOW FLIP.
NICE.
LOOK AT ALL THAT CRUST.
THAT IS IN THE REALM OF UMAMI.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
START BUILDING.
TRUFFLE DUXELLE.
DUDE.
A LITTLE SMOKED BACON,
MINCED.
AND SMOKED GOUDA.
AND THEN, COVER IT.
LET IT MELT.
GET IT TOASTED.
OKAY.
VERY NICE.
TOGARASHI MAYO.
PLEASE.
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT
OF SUN-DRIED TOMATO CONFIT.
YEP.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
WARM IT UP HERE.
OKAY.
DUDE, YOU HAVE GOT
SOME TECHNIQUE HERE.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE BURGER ON.
OKAY.
OKAY, TOP IT OFF.
LOOK AT THAT.
THIS BURGER SHOULD DEFINITELY
DELIVER THE FLAVORS OF UMAMI.
WOW. YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE FIFTH SENSE.
IT TAKES YOU
TO THE NEXT LEVEL.
IT'S RICH. IT'S LIGHT.
SMOKINESS, ACID,
EARTHY TONES.
THAT'S OUT OF THE PARK.
THAT EXCEEDED WHAT
MY EXPECTATIONS WERE GONNA BE.
IT IS IN THE TOP BEST BURGERS
I'VE EVER HAD.
THANK YOU.
MMM.
THAT IS CRAZY, MAN.
LET'S JUST GO
TO A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
(laughs)
QUIET TIME'S OVER...
TALK TO ME.
'CAUSE WE'RE JUST
GETTING STARTED
IN bopNgrill IN CHICAGO.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
(Will)
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK EGGROLL.
THAT'S COOL, DUDE.
A KOREAN SPIN
ON THE SOUTH PHILLY STAPLE.
THERE IS NOTHING ABOUT THAT
I DON'T LIKE.
WE'RE HANGING AT bopNgrill
IN THE ROGERS PARK AREA
OF CHICAGO,
AND I GOT CHEF WILL SONG
COOKING SOME RIGHTEOUS KOREAN
INTO BURGERS AND FRIES...
(man) IT'S REALLY SPECTACULAR,
FUN FOOD.
(woman) I THINK
IT'S AN AWESOME COMBINATION,
COMBINING KOREAN
AND AMERICAN.
ALL OVER THE MENU...
THE FOOD ALL HAS
KIND OF A TWIST TO IT.
ESPECIALLY IN THIS
EAST-MEETS-WEST EXTRAVAGANZA.
(Will)
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK EGGROLL.
I CAN'T STOP EATING.
SUPERGOOD.
THESE EGGROLLS
RIGHT HERE
GOT ME THROUGH
MY NINE MONTHS OF PREGNANCY.
OKAY, WHAT ARE
WE MAKING NEXT?
OUR HOUSE MARINADE...
OKAY.
FOR OUR
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK EGGROLLS.
KOREAN
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK.
WE START OFF
WITH ASIAN PEAR.
PINEAPPLE.
SPRITE.
SO SOME LEMON-LIME SODA.
YOU AND YOUR GARLIC.
DUDE, LISTEN.
I'M KOREAN.
MIRIN.
MIRIN, MIRIN,
ON THE WALL.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
OKAY.
SCALLIONS.
SESAME OIL.
SAYS YOU.
SESAME SEEDS.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
SALT AND PEPPER.
AND WE BLEND.
WHAT ARE WE MARINATING
IN IT?
SLICED RIB EYE.
TALK TO ME.
WE GET A LITTLE BIT
OF SOY.
THAT'S NOT A LITTLE BIT,
BY THE WAY.
JUST A TAD.
BROWN SUGAR.
I LIKE
WHERE THIS IS GOING.
YEAH.
THE MEAT'S GONNA HAVE
A FULL-BLOWN
KOREAN BARBECUE FLAVOR.
YEAH, TRADITIONAL--
WE CALL IT “PROGOGI.”
WHICH IS BASICALLY...
OBOGI? PROGOGI?
YEAH, YEAH.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY
TO TERIYAKI SAUCE.
KOREAN VERSION OF IT.
MARINADE.
WE JUST
INCORPORATE IT COMPLETELY.
AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE?
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE
THE RIB EYE IN IT.
SLICE IT THIN.
WE'RE GONNA ADD SOME ONIONS
AND CARROTS. ADD THE MARINADE.
THAT'S IT.
ON THE FLATTOP?
YEP, FLATTOP
WITH SOME OIL.
(metal dings)
WHAT, IS THAT SOME BELL
YOU DO WHEN YOU...
YEAH, WATCH.
(dinging)
AND THE MARINATED MEAT,
JUST RIGHT ON TOP.
SO YOU'RE GONNA COOK IT ALL,
COOL IT ALL...
RIGHT.
AND THEN WRAP AND ROLL.
DIG IT.
EGGROLL WRAPPER.
EGG WASH.
AMERICAN CHEESE.
FILLING MIX, A NICE LITTLE
HANDFUL IN THE MIDDLE.
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA WRAP.
THAT'S IT.
TWO PER ORDER?
TWO PER ORDER.
THERE YOU GO.
FRY 'EM UP.
SPLIT THEM IN HALF.
THAT'S NUTS.
OH, OH.
CHEESE SAUCE.
SESAME SEEDS, OF COURSE.
YEP.
THAT'S COOL, DUDE.
NICE.
MMM. DUDE.
THERE IS NOTHING ABOUT THAT
I DON'T LIKE.
THERE'S A LOT OF MEAT.
YEAH.
PROGOGI MEAT
IS OUTRAGEOUS.
IS IT NOT OFF THE HOOK?
THAT'S RIGHTEOUS.
PHILLY CHEESESTEAK EGGROLL.
IT'S A GREAT BLEND OF TASTE.
THIS IS KOREAN MEETS AMERICAN.
(woman) THE DELICIOUSNESS OF
THE SANDWICH ALL IN AN EGGROLL--
IT'S AWESOME.
(woman) AMERICAN FOOD LOVERS
AND KOREAN FOOD LOVERS
BOTH CAN BE HAPPY HERE.
YOU CAN'T GET
SOMETHING LIKE THIS ANYWHERE.
THOSE NEXT TWO BUSINESSES NEXT
DOOR, YOU WANT TO JUST GO OVER
AND LET 'EM KNOW THAT THEY'RE
GONNA BE MOVING OUT SOON?
(laughs)
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I'M GONNA TELL 'EM.
I GOT TO GO TELL THOSE PEOPLE
THEY'RE GONNA BE GONE.
UP NEXT, I'M ROLLING THE JEEP
INTO THE LAID-BACK TOWN
OF WAIMANALO, OAHU...
IT IS SWIMSUIT WEATHER
ALL THE TIME HERE.
FOR A BIG-TIME BURGER
THAT DELIVERS...
TOFU MOMENT
ON TRIPLE “D.”
(laughs)
AS PROMISED.
THAT BURGER'S MONEY.
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
ON THE ISLAND OF OAHU.
NOW WHAT DO MOST PEOPLE THINK?
THEY THINK WAIKIKI
AND THE NORTH SHORE.
ME, I DIG COMING
TO THE EAST SIDE.
THIS IS WHERE YOU GET THAT REAL
HAWAIIAN COUNTRY AND CULTURE.
AND I HEAR THERE'S A PLACE
THAT'S EMBODYING ALL OF THAT,
RIGHT HERE
AT SWEET HOME WAIMANALO.
FISH TACOS.
OH, MY GOD.
THE FOOD IS SO GOOD.
(man) EVERYTHING
IS MADE FROM SCRATCH.
IT'S JUST LIKE COMING HOME.
IT'S PERFECT, WITH THE NAME.
WAIMANALO MAGIC--
I CAN'T EXPLAIN IT.
IT COULD HAVE SOMETHING
TO DO WITH THE LOCATION--
BEACHES IN THE FRONT,
FARMLAND IN THE BACK.
EVERYTHING'S A LOT BETTER,
'CAUSE IT'S A LOT FRESHER.
THE GREENS ARE GROWN
ON THE ROOF.
WHERE OWNER JOANNE KAPOLOLU
DIGS HANGING OUT.
SO I CAN ALREADY TELL
SOMETHING ABOUT YOU.
YOU GOT SOME VERY BIG SPIRIT.
YOU GOT A LOT OF ENERGY.
I DO.
SO HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
TWO YEARS.
WE HAD A LITTLE COFFEEHOUSE
BEFORE IN THE '90s.
BUT THE NEW DIGS RIGHT OFF
THE ROAD IN AN OLD GAS STATION
FIT HER FOOD STYLE WAY BETTER.
(woman) THE PHILOSOPHY
THAT JOANNE HAS
IS THAT FARM-TO-TABLE CONCEPT.
AROUND HERE,
IT ALSO MEANS WAVE-TO-TABLE.
YOU GOT IT?
I GOT IT.
THANK YOU, LANCE.
ALOHA.
A LOT OF THE FARMERS
THAT SHE'S BUYING FROM
ARE WITHIN A 10-MILE RADIUS.
AND IT'S NICE TO BE ABLE
TO SUPPORT A RESTAURANT
WITH THAT PHILOSOPHY.
WHERE DID IT COME FROM?
IT COMES FROM ME BEING
A BREAST CANCER SURVIVOR.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO ME
TO MAKE SURE THAT PEOPLE KNEW
THAT FOOD IS RELATED TO WHO WE
ARE ON THE INSIDE, TOO,
IN OUR BODIES.
SO SHE GOT CHEF
AND FORMER SINGER WENDY KINO
ROCKING THAT
GOOD-FOR-YOU GRILL.
FIRING TOFU
BLACK BEAN BURGER.
MY FAVORITE DISH
IS THE TOFU BURGER.
YOU KNOW, I LOVE EATING
ALL TYPES OF MEAT,
BUT YOU KNOW, I CAN'T PASS UP
THIS BURGER.
IN HONOR OF MY SISTER MORGAN--
NAMASTE...
YES.
I GOT TO TRY SOMETHING
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT...
YEP.
SO I WENT
FOR THE TOFU BURGER.
BUT I GOT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU,
NOT A HUGE TOFU BURGER FAN.
I'M GONNA CHANGE
YOUR MIND.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA GRILL
SOME TOFU.
MM-MMM. JUST LOOK
AT THAT GELATINOUS CURD.
OIL ON OUR GRILL.
AND WE'RE JUST BASICALLY
DRYING THIS OUT.
WE WANT TO GET AS MUCH WATER
OUT OF IT AS POSSIBLE.
WE'RE GONNA PRESS IT DOWN.
AND WE JUST WANT IT TO BE
LIKE BEEF JERKY ALMOST.
IT ADDS MORE TEXTURE
TO THE BURGER.
WE ARE GONNA SAUTé
OUR VEGETABLES.
ONION.
I'M GLAD I HAD
THAT FISH TACO EARLIER.
(laughs)
SHREDDED CARROTS.
CHOPPED CELERY.
CHOPPED MUSHROOMS.
STIR THIS AROUND
A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA DO GARLIC.
AND THIS IS A BIG HIT HERE,
HUH, THE TOFU BURGER?
IT'S A BIG HIT.
WE GOT A TOFU MOMENT
ON TRIPLE “D.”
(laughs)
NOW TAKE THIS OFF
TO COOL.
LITERALLY THE TOFU
HAS BEEN DOWN FOR AN HOUR.
PRETTY MUCH DRIED OUT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
TO OUR VEGGIES
BLACK BEANS,
ORGANIC SPINACH,
SOYRIZO.
I'M SURE YOU'VE HAD
CHORIZO SAUSAGE.
VEGAN CHORIZO SAUSAGE.
YEAH.
THIS WILL BE INTERESTING.
YOU KNOW, IT IS SWIMSUIT WEATHER
ALL THE TIME HERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX TOGETHER
OUR SPICES.
SO WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR LIQUID MIXTURE,
WHICH IS LIQUID SMOKE,
LIQUID AMINOS,
AND LEMON JUICE.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA DO
THE DRY MIX--
MINCED ONION, THYME,
MUSTARD, CHILI POWDER,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
CUMIN, CURRY POWDER,
CAYENNE, SALT, PEPPER.
WHISK IT.
AND THAT'S THAT.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND BREAK
THESE UP WITH OUR HANDS.
THIS IS ALL GONNA GO
IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR?
YES.
NEXT UP, T.V.P.--
TEXTURED VEGETABLE PROTEIN.
IT LOOKS LIKE HAMBURGER.
PANKO BREADCRUMBS.
CORNMEAL. CILANTRO.
GOT IT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
MIX THIS UP A LITTLE BIT.
AND THEN THIS
INTO THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
THAT'S A LOT OF WORK
FOR A DANG TOFU BURGER.
IT IS.
THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE
COME FOR.
I FEEL HEALTHY
JUST STANDING NEXT TO IT.
(whistles)
WE'RE GOING TO PLACE THIS
IN HERE.
ADD OUR DRY SPICES
AND OUR WET MIX.
WE JUST WANT--
ARE YOU ON
YOUR TIPPY TOES DOING THIS?
I AM. I CAN'T REACH.
(laughs) IT'S A WORKOUT.
I NEED FOUR ARMS
LIKE YOURS.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
I ONLY HAVE TWO ARMS.
(laughs)
SCOOP AND FORM.
SO...
IT REQUIRES A LITTLE BIT
OF SKILL
TO GET 'EM JUST PERFECT,
YOU KNOW.
(whistles)
(normal voice)
SHE DID A NICE JOB WITH THAT.
WE'RE GONNA OIL OUR PAN,
GET THAT GOING.
AND I WANT IT DARK.
CRISP ON BOTH SIDES...
YEAH.
TO BUILD TEXTURE.
YES, EXACTLY.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
OH, WE ARE
A TEXTURE MACHINE TODAY.
IS THAT REALLY HOW DARK
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE?
YES. YEP.
BUN IS GRILLED.
PUT IT ON
OUR GRILLED HAWAIIAN BUN.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
A LITTLE RED PEPPER AIOLI.
RED PEPPER AIOLI,
RED ONIONS,
ROMA TOMATOES,
AND BABY ROMAINE.
SEE IF WE CAN TRANSFORM YOU.
(laughs)
THIS IS PERFECT.
THIS IS BIG.
CAN I GET A DRUMROLL
OR SOMETHING?
(crunching)
I CAN HEAR THE CRUNCH.
THAT'S MY SNAKE-LIKE JAW
RELEASING.
(laughs)
IT'S OUTRAGEOUS.
I MEAN, GREAT FLAVOR.
YOU COULD PUT THIS
IN FRONT OF THE AVERAGE PERSON
OR EVEN A CHEF.
YOU WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO TELL
IT'S TOFU.
YOU CAN GET THAT KIND OF TEXTURE
AND THAT KIND OF DEPTH
AND THAT KIND OF MEATINESS TO IT
AND HAVE IT HEALTHY?
YEAH.
WE WANT TO TRANSFORM
AS MANY PEOPLE AS WE CAN.
I SIGNED THE PETITION.
I'M ON THE TEAM.
YAY.
THAT BURGER'S MONEY.
MMM!
TOFU BLACK BEAN BURGER
FOR MIKE.
(man) VERY NICE SPICE
AND TASTE TO IT.
IT'S GOT A NICE
CRUNCHY EXTERIOR. PERFECT.
(woman) IT'S AMAZING,
SO FLAVORFUL.
LEGIT.
MM-HMM.
SO WHAT VEGETARIAN DELIGHT
ARE WE COOKING UP NEXT?
YOU GOT ME IN
A VEGGIE MOOD NOW.
YOU'RE GONNA GO BACK THERE
TO THAT SMOKER WITH GERALD
AND MAKE SOME PULLED PORK.
VEGGIE SANDWICH
TO PULLED PORK IN HAWAII?
EXACTLY.
HOW CAN MY LIFE GET ANY BETTER?
WE'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
♪♪
SO WE'RE BACK, TRIPLE “”"
ON THE ISLAND OF OAHU.
WE'RE AT
SWEET HOME WAIMANALO.
DID I GET IT RIGHT?
YEAH.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
BARBECUING IN THE BACKYARD.
CAN YOU BEAT IT?
(man) THE VIEW, THE FOOD IS
GREAT. IT'S JUST A GOOD VIBE.
AFTER SURFING, I CAN COME HERE
AND GET A REALLY NICE
PLATE LUNCH.
THE BEST PLACE YOU'RE GONNA FIND
ON THE EAST SIDE
FOR LOCAL GRINDS.
PULLED PORK PLATE
FOR MATT.
THE PULLED PORK
IS JUST AMAZING.
AND PIT MASTER GERALD BOYER
HAS GOT PLENTY OF ROOM
TO SMOKE IT.
YOU REALLY COOK
OUT HERE?
YEAH, WE SMOKE EVERYTHING
OUT HERE.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
I'M ORIGINALLY FROM SAIPAN,
RIGHT NEXT TO GUAM.
DID YOU DO A LOT
OF BARBECUE THERE...
YEAH.
OR DID YOU
JUST LEARN THIS HERE?
LOTS OF BARBECUE,
LOTS OF SMOKED MEAT.
COOKING OUTSIDE.
YEAH.
THIS IS IT. I GOT TO OPEN
A RESTAURANT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, SO WHAT
ARE WE GONNA MAKE, MAN?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR BEER BARBECUE SAUCE
FOR OUR AALUA PORK,
PULLED PORK.
TOLD YOU THERE WOULD BE A COLD
BEVERAGE INVOLVED IN THIS.
WE HAVE SOME OIL HERE.
WE HAVE SOME RED ONIONS.
WE HAVE
SOME YELLOW ONIONS.
I'VE GOT SOME GARLIC HERE.
I'M GONNA STIR THAT UP
REAL QUICK.
LOCALLY BREWED BEER
FROM BIG ALOHA BREWERY.
FRESH BREWED COFFEE.
KETCHUP.
KETCHUP IS THE BASE
OF THIS?
YEAH.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
WE HAVE
ORANGE JUICE CONCENTRATE.
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
WE HAVE CHIPOTLE PURéE
IN ADOBO SAUCE OVER HERE.
NOW WHERE'D YOU LEARN
TO COOK?
MY MOM'S KITCHEN.
BEST PLACE TO LEARN,
BROTHER.
YEAH.
WE HAVE CHILI POWDER.
MOLASSES.
TOMATO PASTE.
GOT IT.
CUMIN POWDER.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
COCOA POWDER.
SOME SALT.
I HAVE SOME BLACK PEPPER.
FINALLY WE HAVE BROWN SUGAR
TO ROUND IT ALL UP.
21 ITEMS.
AND A LOT OF LOVE.
WE DON'T WORK HERE. WE, UH...
JUST HANG?
WE PUT LOVE INTO ACTION.
NOW I'M GONNA
STIR EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
HOW LONG
DO YOU COOK THIS DOWN?
WHENEVER I'M DONE
HANGING OUT,
THAT'S WHEN I KNOW
THE BARBECUE SAUCE IS DONE.
WHEN YOU'RE DONE
HANGING OUT?
YEAH.
DID YOU WIN THE LOTTERY
TO GET THIS JOB?
ALL RIGHT, G.,
WHAT ARE WE ONTO?
SO I'M CUTTING
SOME PORK BUTT OR PORK SHOULDER
THAT WE'RE GONNA PUT
IN THE SMOKER RIGHT NOW.
I LIKE
TO PORTION THEM OUT
INTO BASEBALL
OR SOFTBALL-SIZED PIECES, YEAH.
I'M GOING
TO MIX MY RUB TOGETHER.
SO HAWAIIAN SEA SALT.
WHITE GRANULATED SUGAR.
GINGER POWDER.
GIVE THAT A GOOD MIX.
OKAY, NOW WE SPRINKLE ON
THE DRY RUB.
YES, WE'RE SPRINKLING
THE DRY RUB ON.
EVERYTHING IS JUST CHILL.
(whistles)
THERE YOU GO.
NOW WHAT'S UP?
SO WE'RE PUTTING OUR
SEASONED PORK INTO OUR SMOKER.
THE RACKS SLIDE OUT.
WE SPACE THE MEAT.
WE GIVE EACH PIECE
A LITTLE BIT OF SPACE.
SO IT HAS A CHANCE
TO GET WRAPPED BY SMOKE.
YES, EXACTLY.
SLIDE IT IN.
HOW LONG'S THIS GONNA GO?
THREE HOURS
IN THE SMOKER.
AND THEN AFTER THE THREE HOURS,
WE BRAISE IT IN BEER AND WATER.
♪♪
ALL RIGHT, SO THEY'VE BEEN ON
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS.
NOW WE DILUTE THE BEER
IN A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
AND THEN I'M GONNA ADD IT
TO THE PAN.
WRAP IT IN PLASTIC
AND FOIL,
BACK IN THE SMOKER
FOR HOW LONG?
AT LEAST FIVE HOURS.
READY TO ROLL.
OW! THAT'S HOT.
HE TOOK THE TOWELS
AND RAN.
THEN WE HAVE
TO PULL THE PORK.
IT COMES RIGHT APART,
NICE AND EASY.
NICE.
OH, NOTHING WRONG
WITH THAT.
AND I LIKE THE BEER FACTOR
TO IT.
THERE'S NEVER ANYTHING WRONG
WHEN YOU HAVE PORK AND BEER.
WHAT'S THE REST OF THE CIRCUS
WE GOT HERE?
SO WE HAVE
OUR BOK CHOY SLAW,
OKINAWA SWEET POTATOES,
AND OUR VERY FAMOUS CORNBREAD.
THIS IS SOME MANGO CHUTNEY
TO GO WITH YOUR SWEET POTATOES.
NOW WE HAVE OUR BEER
BARBECUE SAUCE FOR THE PORK.
PORK'S SUPER TENDER,
NICE LITTLE HINT OF THAT BEER
IN THERE.
THE CORNBREAD'S NICE AND SWEET,
EVERYTHING GOES ALONG WITH IT.
THE BARBECUE SAUCE,
SERIOUSLY, BRO,
THAT'S A WINNER
RIGHT THERE.
MMM. DUDE, THAT'S LIKE
GOOD SOUTHERN BARBECUE...
REALLY?
ON THE ISLAND.
AND YOU GET TO HANG OUT HERE
A STONE'S THROW FROM THE BEACH.
I'LL BE BACK.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
YEAH, LIFE IS GOOD.
LIFE IS REAL GOOD.
IT'S REALLY TENDER
AND MOIST.
(man) THE BARBECUE SAUCE
IS AMAZING,
SMOKY FLAVOR,
JUST A REALLY GOOD DISH.
I GOT A PULLED PORK PLATE
FOR JOANNE.
IT MAKES YOU WANT
TO COME BACK.
(man) IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING
OTHER THAN THE TYPICAL
PLATE LUNCH,
IT'S DEFINITELY
A GOOD PLACE TO COME.
IT'S JUST ONO-LICIOUS.
MAN, IF ANYBODY
WOULD EVER HAVE TOLD ME
I WAS GONNA EAT A TOFU BURGER
AND DIG IT...
I WOULD HAVE BEEN
SHOCKED. YES.
I TELL YOU, MY SISTER
IS WITH ME RIGHT NOW, LAUGHING.
THIS COULD BE
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND VEGANS,”
IF DON'T WATCH OUT.
YES!
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR-TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
WHAT WAS THAT?
YOU GUYS DON'T HAVE
ANY PTERODACTYLS, DO YOU?
(laughs) NO.
UH-HUH.
(woman laughs)
(laughs)