HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LET'S GET
AFTER THIS.
IT'S A FLAVOR-TOWN CRUISE
RIGHT DOWN
THE NEW ENGLAND COAST.
YOU GUYS DO HAVE
A HEART PADDLE KIT
HERE, RIGHT?
IN THE BLUE-BLOOD TOWN
OF CAMBRIDGE, MASSACHUSETTS...
CHUG-A-LUG,
CHUG-A-LUG...
MAKES YOU WANT
TO HI-DE-HO?
THE SOUTHERN STOP...
THAT'S A PERFECT STORM.
DOING WHAT NEEDS
TO BE DONE...
BELLY OF THE PIG.
TO BACON.
CONFIT-ED PORK BELLY...
CORN DOG. YEAH.
CORN DOG. YES.
AND JUST SOUTH
AT FALL RIVER, MASS.,
IT'S SO GOOD.
THE POLISH JOINT
SERVING UP A SPECIALTY...
(bell dings)
HOW MANY DIFFERENT STYLES
OF PIEROGIS DO YOU MAKE?
103 AND CLIMBING.
PERFECTED BY
THE PIEROGI PRINCESS HERSELF.
PATTI PIEROGI!
AND IN
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND...
JUST TRYING
TO HELP OUT, BOSS.
NOT ONE,
BUT TWO ITALIAN JOINTS...
LET'S DO IT.
ON THE VERY SAME STREET...
(cheering)
ROCKIN' OLD SCHOOL...
(Guy) BRACIOLE.
(man) BRACIOLE.
OH, HO HO.
NEW SCHOOL...
I DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
AND GRADUATING KILLER STUFF.
WHEN DO YOU WANT TO START
YOUR COOKING SHOW?
ANYTIME YOU WANT.
CALIFORNIA, HERE I COME.
MAN...
(laughs)
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
OKAY, I'M HERE
ON CAMBRIDGE STREET
IN CAMBRIDGE, MASS., RIGHT
BETWEEN M.I.T. AND HARVARD,
ALMOST RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE.
I'M GOING TO A JOINT
THAT'S GOT A FUNNY LITTLE STORY.
SO IT'S A CAJUN PLACE
FOR LIKE 20, 25 YEARS,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN
THEY DECIDE TO SELL.
AND IT'S GONNA BECOME
A CHINESE RESTAURANT,
EXCEPT THAT ONE OF THE NEIGHBORS
THAT OWNS A BAKERY
DOESN'T WANT THAT TO HAPPEN,
SO SHE BUYS THE JOINT
AND HIRES THIS CRAZY CHEF.
AND WHAT DO THEY NAME THE PLACE?
AFTER THE BIRTHPLACE OF ELVIS.
IT'S A STORY YOU HEAR EVERY DAY.
THIS IS TUPELO.
CATFISH GOING DOWN.
DON'T TELL ANYBODY
ABOUT THIS PLACE,
BECAUSE WE WANT TO KEEP IT
TO OURSELVES.
IT'S GREAT SOUTHERN COOKING.
(woman)
YOU DO NOT SEE
A LOT OF SOUTHERN RESTAURANTS
AROUND HERE.
THIS IS LIKE A BEACON OF LIGHT
IN THE DARKNESS.
FROM OWNER RENEE McLEOD'S
LIGHT BULB IDEA.
YOU SAY, "NO, WE'RE NOT
GONNA LET IT BECOME
A CHINESE RESTAURANT.
WE'RE GONNA BUILD OUR OWN"...
NEW ORLEANS,
SOUTHERN, FUN...
FUNKY JOINT.
FUNKY JOINT, YES.
THAT GETS ITS GROOVE
FROM CHEF REMBS LAYMAN,
A TRUE CHARACTER
THAT WAS RAISED ON HIS MOM'S
CRESCENT CITY COOKING...
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
BUT WHO BRINGS HIS OWN KIND
OF STYLE TO THE PARTY.
THERE'S A "Z"
IN YOUR HEAD.
THAT'S MY FLAIR.
ALWAYS BEEN DOING IT?
NO, 'CAUSE YOU
WERE COMING.
OH, I LOVE THAT.
I NEEDED FLAIR.
WAY TO PUT SOMETHING ON
EXTRA, YOU KNOW?
JUST KINDA...
(laughs)
BUT HE'S PUTTING
THAT FLAIR
INTO THE GUMBO,
THE BEER-BATTER CREPES...
YOU CAN'T MISS THAT
RIGHT THERE.
AND HIS ZIGZAG TAKE
ON BACON...
MMM.
THAT LITERALLY MADE ME
DO A DOUBLE TAKE.
CONFIT-ED PORK BELLY
CORN DOG.
CONFIT-ED
PORK BELLY...
CORN DOG. YEAH.
CORN DOG. YES.
SO WE'RE GONNA DO A CURE
FOR PORK BELLY.
START WITH KOSHER SALT.
BROWN SUGAR.
CURING SALT.
PIG MAGIC SALT.
GROUND MUSTARD,
CAYENNE PEPPER.
(whistles)
YEAH, DUDE.
CUMIN, DRIED THYME,
PAPRIKA,
SMOKED BLACK PEPPER.
AWESOME.
MMM, I LIKE THAT.
BELLY OF THE PIG.
LIKE A SURGEON.
PUT A NICE LITTLE RUB
ON 'EM.
BEAUTY... FUL.
STICK THIS
INTO A, UH, TUB.
STACK 'EM UP.
WRAP 'EM UP.
YEAH.
LET IT SIT FOR 24 HOURS.
WE TAKE IT OUT.
WE'RE GONNA SUBMERGE IT
IN DUCK FAT, ROAST IT OFF.
TWO AND A HALF TO THREE HOURS
OR UNTIL DONE.
NOW WE MAKE THE BATTER.
ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR,
CORNMEAL, SUGAR,
SALT, BAKING POWDER,
BAKING SODA.
WOW.
LIGHTEN IT UP.
(swish)
PAPRIKA.
GETTING A LITTLE ELVIS THERE
AT THE END, DIDN'T YA?
I DID.
BUTTERMILK.
VERY NICE.
WHOLE MILK, HUEVOS,
FINALLY OIL.
COMBINE WELL.
THEN OF COURSE THIS HAS
TO SIT FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
DIG IT.
YEAH, YOU WILL.
LOOK AT THAT, MAN.
YEAH.
"SILA-GOUS"...
GELATINOUS MAXIMUS.
GRAB A SKEWER.
AND NOW WE GRAB
A SKEWER
YEP.
MAKE SURE YOU GET
INSIDE THE MEAT.
CORRECT.
INTO THE DREDGE.
THE CORNMEAL STICKS
TO THE STICKY PIG...
YEP.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
TO THE BATTER.
WE ARE.
HERE WE GO.
WE'RE JUST TRYING TO, LIKE,
BUILD A BARRIER HERE,
SO IT DOESN'T GO
RIGHT TO THE BOTTOM.
THE ANTICIPATION'S
JUST KILLING ME.
IT'S A HUNKA-HUNKA
BURNIN' LOVE.
YOU GUYS DO HAVE
A HEART PADDLE KIT HERE, RIGHT?
YES, WE DO.
YOU'RE ALL SET.
SOME OF THEM, UH,
PICKLED HABANEROS AND ONIONS.
JALAPEÑO AIOLI?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET AFTER THIS.
SMELLS LIKE CORN DOG.
MMM.
THAT'S A PERFECT STORM.
IT JUST HAS THAT REALLY RICH,
INTENSE PORK FLAVOR.
THEN YOU GET THE TEXTURE
AND THE CRUNCH
OF THE--
OF THE BATTER.
THEN EVERYTHING IS CUT
AND PUT INTO ORDER
BY THE PICKLED ONIONS
AND THE HABANEROS.
THAT'S A MUST-TRY.
YEAH.
I SAW THAT ON THE MENU.
I SAID, "I MUST TRY THAT."
AWESOME. SERIOUSLY.
CORN DOG.
(woman)
I LOVE THE DOG.
THERE'S THE RICHNESS
OF THE PORK,
BUT THEN THERE'S
THIS AWESOME CRUNCHINESS
FROM THE OUTSIDE OF THE BATTER.
TO DIE FOR.
ALWAYS CREATIVE STUFF.
GREAT FOOD ALL THE TIME.
IT'S A FUNKY JOINT.
YOU CRUISE IN AND TELL ME
THAT I WOULD FIND A DISH
LIKE THAT,
I'D SAY YOU'RE CRAZY.
AND THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS
I THINK YOU ARE.
A LITTLE.
YEAH, IT TAKES ONE
TO KNOW ONE.
(woman) IF YOU WANT
TO HAVE YOUR TASTE BUDS
COMPLETELY ELECTRIFIED,
THIS IS THE PLACE TO GO.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
THANKS FOR SAVING
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
THANK YOU
FOR COMING.
UP NEXT...
YES!
DOWN THE COAST
TO FALL RIVER, MASS...
EVERYTHING'S
AN "OGI."
WHERE I'M BUSTING OUT
THE SPECIAL EFFECTS...
(imitating
liquid pouring)
AND MY LOVE
OF ALLITERATION...
I OVERPRESSED MY PIEROGI,
AND NOW IT'S A PUCK.
IN MY QUEST
FOR PIEROGI PARADISE.
THAT'S A PARTY-PACKED
PIEROGI.
♪♪
SO I'M ABOUT 50 MILES
SOUTH OF BOSTON
ON THE TAUNTON RIVER
IN A TOWN CALLED FALL RIVER,
WHICH HAPPENS TO BE
THE BIRTHPLACE
OF MY BROTHER FROM
ANOTHER MOTHER--EMERIL LAGASSE.
AND THEY'VE ALSO GOT A JOINT
THAT IS SERVING UP
ONE OF MY FAVORITE
POLISH SPECIALTIES.
THIS IS PATTI'S PIEROGIS.
PRUNE PIEROGI,
CABBAGE AND PORK,
AND MAC AND CHEESE.
(bell dings)
WICKED GOOD.
WICKED GOOD?
WICKED.
HER CREATIVITY
HAS NO BOUNDS.
THAT'S 'CAUSE VETERAN WAITRESS
PATTI GEARY...
ONE FRENCHOGI,
ONE PIZZA, AND ONE MAC.
TURNED HER LIFELONG
PIEROGI PASTIME
INTO A POLISH FOOD PALACE
IN '09.
I HAVEN'T MET, LIKE,
A PIEROGI PRINCESS.
I WANTED TO HAVE FUN
WITH THE PIEROGI.
YOU HAVE SO MUCH FUN
WITH THE PIEROGI
THAT YOU HAVE
A PIEROGI CHARACTER
THAT DANCES AROUND
OUT FRONT.
YES.
GIVE ME THE PAST
OF PIEROGIS.
WELL, IT'S A POLISH
RAVIOLI.
OKAY.
HOW MANY DIFFERENT STYLES
OF PIEROGIS DO YOU MAKE?
103 AND CLIMBING.
NOT ALWAYS AVAILABLE.
NO, THEY COME AND GO.
EVERYTHING'S AN "OGI."
VERY NICE. SO YOU HAVE
PIEROGIS OF THE PAST
AND PIEROGIS
OF THE PRESENT.
YES, AND THE FUTURE,
'CAUSE I'M ALWAYS THINKING
OF ONE IN MY HEAD.
THE MAC AND CHEESE ORDER--
ALMOST UP.
LOVE IT.
ENDLESS FLAVORS.
BUT THE PIEROGI
THAT'S ALWAYS POPULAR...
(Patti)
CABBAGE AND PORK!
IT'S THE BEST.
IS THE ONE PASSED DOWN
FROM PATTI'S POLISH GRANNY.
OKAY.
WE ARE MAKING
CABBAGE AND PORK.
THIS IS TRADITIONAL.
CAN I PARTICIPATE
IN THE PIEROGIS?
SURE.
WE'RE GONNA DUMP
THE FLOUR IN.
ONE EGG.
ADD MY MILK.
OKAY.
AND THEN
I SLOWLY POUR IT IN.
HAVE YOU ALWAYS HAD
PIEROGI PASSION?
YES.
I STARTED COOKING
WHEN I WAS 12 YEARS OLD.
YEAH.
THE KITCHEN WAS MY COMFORT ZONE
AND STILL IS TODAY.
NOW I TAKE THE DOUGH.
SO YOU GOT
A SHEETER.
OKAY, SO I'M GONNA SPRINKLE
A LITTLE FLOUR BACK HERE.
BALL IN. TAKE IT OUT.
OKAY,
NOW WE GO STUFF IT?
YES.
OKAY. BUTTER?
MARGARINE.
REALLY?
YEAH, MARGARINE.
YOUR FAMILY'S RECIPE
INVOLVES MARGARINE?
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
THINGS WERE POOR IN THOSE DAYS.
CHOPPED ONIONS,
GROUND PORK,
SAUERKRAUT.
SO I'M GONNA
STIR-FRY THIS A BIT,
GET EVERYTHING BROWN
IN THERE.
ONION POWDER.
(imitating shaking)
DONE.
DID YOU JUST THROW IN
YOUR OWN...
MY OWN SOUND?
I LOVE THAT. YEAH.
YEAH, I'M GONNA DO IT AGAIN.
GARLIC POWDER.
(imitating shaking)
BLACK PEPPER.
THAT--YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S IT. WORCESTERSHIRE.
(imitating
liquid pouring)
(laughs)
SOY SAUCE.
(imitating
liquid pouring)
THIS ONE TAKES
A LITTLE MORE. OKAY, GOOD.
I HAVE CABBAGE NOW.
OKAY. THERE YOU GO.
BOILED, STEAMED?
BOILED.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF CAYENNE?
CAYENNE WORKS WELL
WITH CABBAGE.
IT BRINGS OUT THE FLAVOR.
STIR-FRY...
STIR-FRY.
TILL EVERYTHING'S BLENDED,
AND IT'S DONE.
ALL DONE.
LET IT COOL, AND THAT'S
READY TO GET STUFFED
INTO A PIEROGI.
THAT'S--YES.
LET'S DO IT.
LOOK AT THIS.
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS AWESOME.
TAKE THIS?
SO A PIECE OF DOUGH
ON TOP OF THE CUTOUT.
OKAY.
A SCOOP
OF MY CABBAGE FILLING.
TUCK IT IN LIKE THAT.
OKAY.
GIVE IT A TURN.
AND OUT POPS
A PIEROGI.
PIEROGI.
YES.
LOOK AT THAT.
PERFECTLY PRESSED
PIEROGI PORTION BY PATTI.
(laughs) OKAY.
OKAY, SO CAN I TRY?
SURE. TUCK IT IN.
OKAY. TUCK IT IN.
NICE... (mumbling)
AND THEN I JUST GIVE IT
THE OLD ONE-TWO?
THAT'S IT.
AND WHERE'D IT GO?
AWESOME.
I OVERPRESSED MY PIEROGI,
AND NOW IT'S A PUCK.
I HAVE A POT
OF BOILING WATER.
DROP IT IN.
SO NOW I TAKE MY PIEROGI PUCK
AND JUST DROP IT IN.
LIKE A FISH.
SWIM, FISH.
(laughs)
IT WILL RISE TO THE TOP
WHEN IT'S COOKED.
SWIM, PIEROGI.
MINE'S FLOATING.
YEP, IT LOOKS LIKE IT GOT HIT
BY A CAR, THOUGH.
SO IT'S TENDER.
I ADD A LITTLE BUTTER.
PUT 'EM ON.
LET IT SIZZLE.
LET IT BUILD
SOME CRUST.
YEP.
OKAY, SO NOW THEY'RE FRIED
ON BOTH SIDES,
NICE GOLDEN BROWN.
HOT. MMM.
YES.
IT'S SO GOOD. YOU GET
A LITTLE BIT OF THE ACID
OF THE SAUERKRAUT AND...
THEN YOU GET THE CABBAGE,
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH
THAT'S IN THERE.
THE CRUST--
IT'S OUTSTANDING. MMM.
I'M IN PIEROGI PARADISE.
(laughs)
HOW MANY
YOU THINK YOU CAN EAT?
ON A GOOD DAY
MAYBE SIX OR SEVEN.
AND ON A BAD DAY
12 OR 15?
PROBABLY.
VERY NICE.
(all laughing)
I'M HANGING OUT
WITH MY BUDDY NICHOLAS,
WHO JUST TURNED 10
AND HAS BEEN CANCER-FREE
FOR HOW LONG NOW?
THREE YEARS.
I MET HIM FOUR YEARS AGO
WHEN WE WERE DOING TRIPLE "D"
IN CONNECTICUT.
THIS KID IS AMAZING.
YOU'RE THE MAN.
(imitates explosion)
BETTER MAKE A "GUYOGI."
YOU KNOW THAT HAS SPAGHETTI
AND MEATBALLS IN IT.
GUYOGI--
HERE WE COME.
SPICY.
ALL RIGHT.
YES!
COMING UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO FEDERAL HILL
IN PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND...
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN.
HOW DO WE DO IT
HERE AT ANGELO'S?
FOR A JOINT THAT'S BEEN
STAYING TRUE TO ITS ROOTS...
WOW, LOOK AT THAT.
SINCE THE 1920s.
FALLS APART.
♪♪
SO HERE I AM,
THE WORLD-FAMOUS FEDERAL HILL
ON ATWELLS AVENUE.
I MEAN,
I GUESS YOU COULD CALL THIS
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND'S,
"LITTLE ITALY."
I MEAN, THERE'S SO MUCH HISTORY
AND SO MUCH CHARACTER,
AND NOT TO MENTION,
IN A MILE AND 1/2,
OVER 30 RESTAURANTS.
SO TODAY YOU GET
A DOUBLE FEATURE.
THAT'S RIGHT--
THE 15-YEAR-OLD MEDITERRANEO.
BUT FIRST UP,
THE OLD SCHOOL--
FROM 1924,
THIS IS ANGELO'S.
VEGGIE LASAGNA IS UP!
IT'S JUST THAT HOMEMADE TASTE
THAT YOU WOULD GET
IN YOUR MOM'S KITCHEN.
HERE'S YOUR
CHICKEN PARM.
(woman) THANK YOU.
EVERY PERSON
IN THE STATE OF RHODE ISLAND
HAS BEEN TO ANGELO'S
AT LEAST ONCE IN THEIR LIFE.
WHO'S BEEN HERE
BEFORE?
(cheering)
THAT'S THE KIND OF LOVE
THIS PLACE HAS BEEN GETTING
SINCE ANGELO MASTRODICASA
FIRST OPENED IN 1924.
I LOVE THE FACT
THAT I AM BRINGING MY KIDS
TO THE SAME PLACE
THAT MY GRANDFATHER
BROUGHT HIS KIDS TO.
VEAL PARM WITH SPAGHETTI!
AND WHEN BOB ANTIGNANO
TOOK OVER IN '88,
HE GOT THE FAMILY BLESSING
TO GO BACK TO ITS ROOTS.
WE WENT BACK TO THE ORIGINAL
RECIPES FROM 1924.
WHICH MEANT DISHES THAT ROLLED
WITH THE TIMES.
(Bob) MEATBALLS AND FRIES!
SERIOUSLY?
SERIOUSLY.
DURING THE DEPRESSION,
WE HAD TO FIND A WAY OF FEEDING
THE PEOPLE ON FEDERAL HILL.
THEY WOULD GET TWO MEATBALLS,
A LITTLE BIT OF FRENCH FRIES,
AND THE STARCH
WOULD FILL THEM UP,
AND THEY'D BE ABLE TO MAKE IT
THROUGH ANOTHER DAY.
EGGPLANT SPECIAL!
THIS JOINT IS TRADITIONAL
WITH A CAPITAL "T"
WITH ITALIAN-AMERICAN CLASSICS
LIKE PASTINE SOUP,
VEAL AND PEPPERS,
OR THEIR SICILIAN TAKE
ON THINLY SLICED BEEF.
BRACIOLE IS UP!
THE MEAT IS ABSOLUTELY TENDER
AND DELICIOUS.
ALL RIGHT,
FIRE IT UP.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR BASIC SAUCE FIRST,
OR AS WE WOULD CALL IT,
A GRAVY.
WE START
WITH PORK TRIMMINGS, OIL.
AND ONCE THAT BROWNS UP,
WE ADD SOME GARLIC.
A LITTLE ROUGH CHOP.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR ONION,
HOT RED PEPPER SEEDS.
AND WE'RE GONNA
SAUTé THIS UP.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
LOOK AT THAT.
COOKING THAT PORK DOWN,
ALL THE FLAVOR COMING OUT.
NOW ONCE THIS IS DONE,
READY FOR THE SAUCE.
HIT IT.
6 NUMBER 10 CANS
OF TOMATO SAUCE.
EASY WITH THAT NICE SHIRT.
(laughs)
JUST TRYING
TO HELP OUT, BOSS.
NOW TIME FOR WATER?
IT IS, YES.
RIGHT TO THE TOP.
AND THEN WE'LL STIR IT
REALLY GOOD.
AND THEN WE'LL PUT
ALL OUR SPICES IN.
SALT.
BLACK PEPPER,
OREGANO,
GRANULATED GARLIC.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF BASIL.
YES.
SO IT'S GONNA GO
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS,
SIMMER, AND THEN IT'LL BE READY
FOR THE BRACIOLE.
BRACIOLE.
OH, HO HO.
GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN. HOW DO WE
DO IT HERE AT ANGELO'S?
WELL, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE STUFFING. WE USE SALT PORK.
OKAY.
LITTLE BLACK PEPPER,
PARSLEY...
(whistles)
CRUSHED RED PEPPERS,
AND GARLIC.
THIS IS VERY STRONG.
BRING THIS ALL TOGETHER.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA
GET A BRACIOLE
THAT WE HAND-CUT STILL
HERE AT ANGELO'S.
WHEN WE ROLE THE BRACIOLE OUT,
WE'RE GONNA USE JUST A BIT.
THAT'S PLENTY.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
THIS IS VERY, VERY STRONG.
AND YOU'RE GONNA
TIE THESE OFF.
AND WE'RE GONNA
IN THE POT?
IN THE POT.
GONNA BROWN 'EM OFF,
STACK 'EM UP.
WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME CELERY
AND SOME ONIONS.
OKAY.
SOME WATER.
BROWN IT UP A LITTLE BIT
AND GO FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
AND A LITTLE RED PEPPER SEEDS.
AND WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
A HOMEMADE PASTA.
IT'S AN EGG NOODLE
MADE FOR US RIGHT HERE
ON THE AVENUE.
OKAY. DOWN?
DOWN.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THE BRACIOLE IS READY.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THAT OUT ON A PLATE,
GONNA TAKE THIS
RIGHT OFF.
WOW,
LOOK AT THAT.
ALL RIGHT, GUY,
WE'RE ALL SET.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE HOMEMADE PASTA ON THE PLATE.
BRACIOLE,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE SAUCE.
AND THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
LOOK AT THAT.
JUST FALLS APART.
(chuckles)
THE CENTER'S THE KICKER.
THE CENTER OF THAT IS WHERE
YOU GET THAT SALT PORK,
ALL THAT REAL DEEP FLAVOR.
TO ME, FRESH-MADE PASTA
IS THE KEY. MMM.
SALUTE. SALUTE.
(Bob) BRACIOLE IS UP!
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP,
MY MOTHER USED TO MAKE THESE.
IT REMINDS ME EVERY TIME
I COME IN HERE.
EVERYTHING'S ALWAYS HOT,
FRESH, FAST, AND CONSISTENT.
IT'S A GOOD
FAMILY RESTAURANT.
NICE JOB, BOB.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I DIG IT, MAN.
UP NEXT, WE'RE COMING BACK
TO THE HILL,
'CAUSE WHAT'S BETTER
THAN ITALIAN?
YOU GOT IT--MORE ITALIAN.
SPAGHETTI ALLE VONGOLE.
IT'S LIKE POETRY.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR!
MM!
♪♪
THAT WAS JUST WHAT I EXPECTED--
ANGELO'S OLD-SCHOOL
MEATBALLS AND BRACIOLE.
NOW IT'S TIME TO GO NEW SCHOOL--
ACROSS THE STREET
TO MEDITERRANEO.
(man) CHICKEN PICCATA.
I'M ITALIAN,
AND THIS TASTES LIKE HOME.
(man) TAGLIATELLE
ALLA BOLOGNESE.
IT WAS REPRESENTATIVE
OF WHAT I REMEMBER
OF AUTHENTIC ITALIAN FOOD.
JUST ALL REAL DEAL.
ALL REAL DEAL, YES.
WHICH IS EXACTLY
HOW ITALIAN-BORN OWNER
GIAN MARROCCO PLANNED IT.
I MEAN, EVEN THOUGH YOU'RE
KIND OF IN A TOURISTY AREA,
YOU'D BE HARD-PRESSED TO TELL ME
YOU WEREN'T IN ITALY.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES US DIFFERENT
FROM EVERYBODY ELSE.
AND IT ALL STARTS IN BACK
WITH GIAN'S LONGTIME FRIEND
CHEF MICHELE CALISE.
THAT IS ABOUT
AS ITALIAN-SOUNDING A NAME
AS YOU CAN GET.
I THINK IN ITALIAN,
AND I DO EVERYTHING IN ITALIAN.
YOU DREAM IN ITALIAN.
I DREAM IN ITALIAN.
AND HE DEFINITELY COOKS
IN ITALIAN.
SPAGHETTI
ALLE VONGOLE!
A PASTA DISH FROM THE REGION
OF CAMPANIA.
I'M GONNA MAKE SPAGHETTI
ALLE VONGOLE WHITE SAUCE.
LET'S DO IT.
WE ADD ABOUT 2 TABLESPOONS
OF EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
A "GLOVE," GLOVE AND A HALF
OF SLICED GARLIC.
CLOVE.
PEPERONCINO.
SO A LITTLE
CHILI FLAKE.
CHILI FLAKES. THEN WE ADD
OUR LITTLENECKS.
THE LITTLENECK CLAMS THAT HAVE
BEEN CLEANED, SCRUBBED.
YES, AND PURGED.
WE WANT TO DEGLAZE IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WHITE WINE,
ANY TYPE OF WHITE WINE
YOU HAVE AT HOME.
BUT YOU GOTTA AT LEAST
WANT TO DRINK IT.
IF YOU WON'T DRINK IT,
DON'T COOK WITH IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY.
I ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF CLAM JUICE.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
I DON'T LET
THE LITTLENECKS BURN.
PUT A COVER
TO THE PAN...
OKAY.
SO THAT WAY
IT CREATES A STEAM.
THAT WAY--
(imitating Italian accent)
CREATES A STEAM.
STEAM SO THE CLAM
CAN OPEN.
(normal voice) DO YOU
GET THE ENTHUSIASM?
THAT'S ITALIAN.
I GOT IT, MAN.
(speaking indistinctly)
I'M--I CAN--THIS IS--
IT'S LIKE POETRY.
SO AT THIS POINT WHILE
IT'S COOKING, RIGHT...
RIGHT.
YOU WANT TO DROP
YOUR PASTA.
WHEN THE CLAMS ARE OPEN,
ALL RIGHT...
OKAY.
WE ADD ALSO BABY CLAMS
TO IT--TO IT.
OKAY.
JUST WANT TO ADD
SOME SALT...
OKAY.
AND SOME BLACK PEPPER.
READY TO PLATE, AND WE PUT
THE CLAMS ALL AROUND.
DRAIN THE PASTA WELL.
RIGHT INTO THE PAN.
I ADD SOME
ITALIAN FLAT PARSLEY.
ITALIAN FLAT PARSLEY--
THE ONLY KIND OF PARSLEY
I LIKE.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT I LIKE TO DO ALSO
BEFORE I SERVE IT--
I LET IT COOK
FOR ONE MORE MINUTE.
THAT WAY THE SAUCE
WILL COAT THE PASTA.
IT BECOMES NICE AND, YOU KNOW,
COATED AND CREAMY.
AND IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
TELL ME YOU DON'T
LOVE THIS GUY.
BEFORE I SERVE IT,
I LIKE TO ADD
SOME MORE
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
JUST A TOUCH.
JUST A LITTLE--
AT THIS POINT
I'M READY TO PLATE IT.
NESTING THE PASTA,
AND THEN POURING
ALL THOSE BEAUTIFUL...
CLAM JUICE ON TOP.
RIGHT ON.
AND VOILà.
THAT'S SPAGHETTI
ALLE VONGOLE.
SO TAKE A LOOK AT THAT.
ALL THAT JUICE.
NO CREAM, NO BUTTER,
NO NADA.
NOPE.
JUST SIMPLE GOODNESS.
(slurping)
MMM. A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT,
LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC.
COOKED THE CLAMS
JUST TO WHEN THEY OPEN UP.
ADD THOSE BABY CLAMS
RIGHT AT THE END.
THE PASTA
IS AL DENTE PERFECT.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
I MEAN, I DON'T GET
SPEECHLESS THAT OFTEN.
MMM.
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR!
HERE WE ARE,
SPAGHETTI ALLE VONGOLE.
THANK YOU.
CLAMS CAN KIND OF BE BORING,
BUT NOT HERE.
SPAGHETTI ALLE VONGOLE.
(man) IT'S EVERYTHING
FROM THE FOOD
TO THE WAITSTAFF
TO THE OWNER.
YOU WALK IN THE DOOR
JUST LIKE YOU'RE FAMILY.
BROTHER...
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OUTSTANDING.
AND YOU...
THANK YOU.
WHEN DO YOU WANT TO START
YOUR COOKING SHOW?
ANYTIME YOU WANT.
MAN...
CALIFORNIA,
HERE I COME.
(laughs)
DON'T LET GIANNI
HEAR THAT.
OH, I KNOW.
KILLER.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪ I WANT PIEROGI ♪
(laughter)