I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
OH, MOMMY.
I'M LIKE A DOG DOING TRICKS
FOR SOME SAVORY TREATS.
OHH, THAT'S
GONNA BE GOOD.
IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE...
JAZZ HANDS?
JAZZ HANDS.
A HOLE-IN-THE-WALL JOINT...
YES.
SERVING UP
SOUTHERN-FRIED STAPLES...
A LOBSTER CORNDOG.
ONLY IN MEMPHIS.
WITH A CHEF
THAT DIGS GETTING DOWN.
WOW, THIS IS A FULL
FLOOR SHOW, ISN'T IT?
IN CHICAGO, ILLINOIS...
ARE YOU READY
TO TASTE THE FORBIDDEN?
THE HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM...
CAN YOU LOOK
AT THE SMELL?
LOOK AT THE SMELL.
ROCKIN' OUT
THE REAL-DEAL CUBAN.
(imitating Tony Montana) NOW
YOU'RE TALKING TO ME, BABY,
AND THAT I LIKE.
AND IN ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND...
LET'S GO.
THE LOCALS' LOCAL SPOT...
"D. PUB,"
AS WE CALL IT.
THE D. PUB,
IF YOU'RE ON THE IN.
GETTING TWISTED...
WITH THEIR TAKE ON BARBECUE.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
LOVINGLY MASSAGE THIS IN.
DID YOU HAVE TO SAY
"LOVINGLY"?
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I LOVE CUBAN FOOD.
WE'RE TALKING THE TRADITION.
WE'RE TALKING THE FLAVOR.
THE ONLY PROBLEM IS YOU CAN'T
FIND IT EVERYWHERE, SO HERE I AM
IN THE ROSCOE VILLAGE AREA
OF CHICAGO
ABOUT 15 MINUTES NORTH
OF THE DOWNTOWN AREA.
I HEAR THEY GOT A CUBAN JOINT
THAT'S ROCKIN' IT OUT.
THEY'RE ROCKING IT OUT,
I'M CHECKIN' IT OUT.
THIS IS 90 MILES CUBAN CAFé.
(man) OXTAIL.
GREAT, GREAT FOOD.
FRICASE DE POLLO?
YOU JUST FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE IN CUBA.
YOU FEEL THE AUTHENTICNESS.
AND YOU DON'T GET
ANY MORE AUTHENTIC
THAN ALBERTO GONZALEZ.
I LEFT CUBA IN 1980
IN THE MARIEL BOATLIFT.
LEFT YOUR HOUSE,
LEFT EVERYTHING?
EXACTLY.
EVERYTHING EXCEPT THE LOVE
OF THE FOOD HE GREW UP WITH.
28 YEARS LATER, HE DECIDED
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
(Alberto) I WAS
IN THE MORTGAGE BUSINESS.
MY WIFE AND I, WE WERE
LOOKING FOR OUR NEXT VENTURE.
IN 2008, THEY WENT OUT
ON A LIMB--WAY OUT.
NEVER BEEN IN
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
EVER IN YOUR LIFE.
NEVER IN MY LIFE.
WHERE'D THE RECIPES
COME FROM?
MY GRANDMOTHER.
REALLY?
YEAH.
WHAT IS CUBAN FOOD? HOW WOULD
YOU EXPLAIN IT TO SOMEBODY?
FULL OF FLAVOR.
I THINK IT'S NOT SPICY.
NOT SPICY.
RICH AND FULL
OF FLAVOR.
IT'S JUST SIMPLE INGREDIENTS
AND JUST TASTES DELICIOUS.
(Alberto) FRICASE DE POLLO.
IT'S WINNER, WINNER
CHICKEN DINNER CUBAN-STYLE.
WE'RE MAKING OUR RUB FOR
OUR CHICKEN--FRICASE DE POLLO.
SEASON SALT.
ALL OF THAT?
ALL OF THAT, MY FRIEND.
WE HAVE PEPPER, OREGANO,
AND THEN WE GOT
THE COMINO.
IT'S JUST A BASIC RUB.
SO NOW WE START RUBBING
OUR CHICKEN SO IT'S ALL OVER.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S IT.
AND HOW ARE WE
GONNA COOK THIS CHICKEN?
WE'RE GONNA SEAR IT.
OLIVE OIL.
HERE, LET'S SEAR IT.
PUT A LITTLE
CRUST ON IT,
BUT WE'RE NOT GONNA
COOK IT ALL THE WAY OFF.
NOW WE ADD WATER
AND WAIT FOR IT TO BOIL.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR SOFRITO.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OIL.
JUST WAIT FOR THE OIL
TO GET A LITTLE WARMER HERE.
WE ADD THE ONIONS. WE ADD
GREEN PEPPER, RED PEPPER.
WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL HERE
WITH GARLIC.
GARLIC.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
WE STIR THIS.
NOW THE COMINO.
JUST GONNA SWEAT THESE DOWN,
NOT CARAMELIZE THEM.
AND THEN DUMP THAT IN
ON TOP OF THE CHICKEN?
EXACTLY.
NOW WE'RE ADDING
TOMATO PASTE, OREGANO,
ANNATTO, CHICKEN STOCK,
AND WE'LL WAIT FOR IT TO COOK
FOR 45 MINUTES.
THEN WE'LL COME BACK TO IT
AND WE ADD A COOKING WINE.
ADD SOME POTATOES AND OLIVES.
SEAR IT ALL TOGETHER.
AND THEN WE'LL COOK IT
FOR 30 MORE MINUTES.
NOW IT'S READY FOR SERVING.
CAN YOU LOOK AT THE SMELL?
LOOK AT THE SMELL.
THE TONY MONTANA HOUR.
(imitating Tony Montana)
I TOLD YOU TO TELL THEM
YOU WERE IN A SANITARIUM.
LOOK HOW BEAUTIFUL
RIGHT HERE.
WE ADD OUR YELLOW RICE--
HOW BEAUTIFUL THAT LOOKS,
SWEET PLANTAINS,
AND WE ARE READY.
(normal voice)
OHH. MMM.
YOU GET THE BRINE
AND THE ACID OF THE OLIVE,
AND THEN YOU GET THE CHICKEN--
THE PAN DRIPPINGS,
THAT SAUCE THAT IT COOKS IN--
OH, OUTRAGEOUS.
NOW IF YOU GRAB
A PIECE OF SWEET PLANTAIN
AND MIX IT ALL TOGETHER...
MM-HMM.
BLENDS IT UP REAL NICE. IT SEALS
IT, YEAH. IT SEALS IT, YEAH.
OH, IS THAT HOW YOU DO IT?
THE OLIVE.
MMM. OHH.
THIS TAKES THE CAKE, MAN.
THE OLIVES ARE THE KEY, THOUGH.
THAT'S WHAT SEALS
THE DEAL.
MMM. THAT IS MONEY,
SERIOUSLY.
BUT WE'RE JUST GETTING
UP TO SPEED AT 90 MILES.
PUERCO DE ASADO.
I HAVE ONE
WORD--"TASTY-LICIOUS."
OH, I BELIEVE IT.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
AT 90 MILES CUBAN CAFé
IN CHICAGO, ILLINOIS,
THEY'RE GOING AUTHENTIC
WITH THE SOUND,
THE MOVES, AND DEFINITELY
THE FLAVORS OF HAVANA.
YOU JUST FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE GOING BACK IN TIME
AND YOU'RE GOING TO CUBA,
AND I FEEL LIKE MY GRANDPARENTS,
HOW THEY GREW UP
AND HOW THEY ATE.
(man) THEY USE, UH, THE WORDS
"TASTE THE FORBIDDEN"
BECAUSE I THINK IF YOU'RE NOT
FROM CUBA, YOU CAN'T GO THERE.
YOU CAN'T EXPERIENCE THEIR FOOD,
THEIR FLAVORS, THEIR SPICES.
ARE YOU READY TO TASTE
THE FORBIDDEN?
YOU'RE GONNA LOOK
THE TASTE OF FORBIDDEN.
ARE YOU READY TO TASTE--
ARE--ARE YOU YOU READY?
YOU'RE GONNA LOOK THE--
YOU'RE GONNA LOOK
THE TASTE OF FORBIDDEN.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR PUERCO
ROAST DE ASADO--ROASTED PORK.
ROASTED PORK.
CUBANS, WE'RE VERY SWEET,
SO WE USE EVERYTHING SUGARCANE,
AND WE GIVE IT
A REAL NICE SWEET TASTE.
WE ADD THE PRUNES FIRST.
I HAVEN'T HAD A PRUNE
IN A LONG TIME.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
THE BACON,
HAM OFF THE BONE,
THE SUGAR--SUGARCANE,
TWO OF THOSE.
THE COLORFUL GUAYABA. THIS IS
ONE OF THOSE THINGS THAT WE HAD
IN THE BACKYARD OF MY HOUSE,
WHICH IS A GUAVA TREE.
THIS IS THE BEST PART--I LOVE
THE FIZZLE OF THE MALTA.
THE MALTA IS THE MALT. IT'S
SORT OF LIKE A GUINNESS BEER,
BUT WITH NO ALCOHOL.
IT DOES--IT TASTES
LIKE FLAT GUINNESS.
A STRONG,
PRUNE-Y ROOT BEER.
THAT'S A GREAT
ADVERTISING.
OOH, HEY, YOU LOOK
THIRSTY AND TIRED.
HOW ABOUT A STRONG,
PRUNE-Y ROOT BEER?
(laughing)
(bell dings)
THIS IS GONNA BE
A RUB FOR OUR PORK.
SO ARE WE GONNA
PURéE THIS?
NO, BASICALLY IT'S
GONNA GO RIGHT IN THERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
RUB THAT ON THE PORK.
WE'RE GONNA RUB,
YEAH, THE PRUNES.
PRUNE NUGGETS ARE GONNA
GO ON THE PORK.
EXACTLY.
(imitating Tony Montana)
NOW YOU'RE TALKING TO ME, BABY,
AND THAT I LIKE. (normal voice)
WHERE'S THE PORK BUTT?
THE PORK BUTT--
LET'S GO.
SAY HELLO
TO MY LITTLE FRIEND.
THAT'S WEIRD, OKAY?
(laughing)
WE'RE GONNA GO
RIGHT IN HERE.
WE DON'T WANT TO GO THROUGH,
'CAUSE WE WANT THE JUICES
TO STAY RIGHT IN THERE.
YOU CREATE SOME POCKETS
SO ALL THESE FLAVORS
ARE GONNA GET
DOWN IN THERE.
EXACTLY. SALT.
SO WE THROW OUR BEAUTIFUL
RUB RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS ABOUT AS FAR FROM
A RUB AS I'VE EVER SEEN.
BASICALLY WE'RE CUBAN.
YOU KNOW, WE MAKE UP
OUR OWN VOCABULARY HERE.
LOOK HOW BEAUTIFUL IT IS.
WE GET THE SOUR ORANGE JUST TO
BALANCE OUT ALL THE SWEETNESS.
SOUR ORANGE IS
ACTUALLY A FRUIT,
AND IF YOU CAN'T GET
SOUR ORANGE, YOU CAN MIX
A LITTLE BIT OF ORANGE JUICE
AND LEMON JUICE TOGETHER.
BANANA LEAVES
WE COVER SO WE COULD--
KEEP THE MOISTURE
IN THERE.
SO WE COULD COOK
REAL--EXACTLY.
A LITTLE FOIL
ON TOP OF THAT.
SO GIVE US A NICE
LITTLE TONY MONTANA
"NOW WE'RE GONNA COOK IT."
(imitating Tony Montana)
NOW WE'RE GONNA COOK IT.
(normal voice)
THE PORK IS READY,
IT'S BEEN COOKING
FOR 5 HOURS AT 350.
WE'RE GONNA OPEN HIM UP
RIGHT HERE. LOOK AT THIS.
THAT'S PERFECTION,
MY FRIEND.
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT.
LOOK AT THAT. LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS ALL GONNA GET SHREDDED,
SOME OF THE JUICES INCORPORATED.
EXACTLY.
CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
THROW IT ON THE FLATTOP,
CRISP UP, RICE AND BEANS.
EXACTLY. WE'RE READY
FOR PLATING.
(whistles)
LOOK AT THAT.
SERIOUSLY?
WE GOT THE WHITE RICE.
WE GOT THE PLANTAINS.
WE GOT THE BEANS
RIGHT THERE.
THE BEANS ARE
MY GRANDMOTHER'S RECIPE.
A VERY RICH DISH. A LITTLE BIT
MORE ON THE SWEET SIDE.
BUT BETWEEN THE PRUNES
AND ALL THE SUGAR
AND THE CARAMELIZED ONIONS, YOU
NEED THIS BALANCE OF THE RICE...
AND THE BEANS TO KIND OF
PARLAY IT ALL TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHEN IT REALLY
STARTS WORKING.
WELL, THAT'S BASICALLY
THE KEY TO CUBAN FOOD.
YOU HAVE
TO MIX EVERYTHING.
YOU GOT TO BRING IT TOGETHER
TO FUSE ALL THOSE FLAVORS.
REALLY NICE DISH.
PUERCO ROAST DE ASADO.
IT'S JUICY. I LIKE
TO EAT IT WITH THE PLANTAINS.
(man) THE PORK HAS
SO MANY COMPLEX FLAVORS.
YOU COULD BUILD FLAVOR
UPON FLAVOR.
I HAVE ONE WORD--
"TASTY-LICIOUS."
THIS MAKES YOU FEEL
LIKE YOU'RE IN CUBA.
AND I APPRECIATE
THAT YOU GUYS HAVE, UH,
INTRODUCED IT TO
THIS GREATER CHICAGO AREA.
I FEEL VERY PROUD THAT
WE'RE ABLE TO DO THAT.
SO TAKE US AWAY WITH
A LITTLE GOOD-BYE DANCE.
HOW DO--HOW--
HOW DOES THAT GO?
IT GOES LIKE THIS.
90 MILES TO CUBA.
90 MILES, BABY.
COME TRY
THE FORBIDDEN DANCE.
(cheering)
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED DOWN
TO MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE...
YOU BUILD IT,
AND THEY WILL COME.
FOR SOME FUNKY TWISTS...
CAN I GET A LITTLE, UH,
JOHN CANDY BEFORE WE GO?
ALL RIGHT.
ON SOME GOOD OLD
SOUTHERN STAPLES.
MMM.
♪♪
(trolley horn honking)
OH, I DIG COMING DOWN
TO MEMPHIS.
I MEAN, SO MUCH HISTORY, AND
SOME GREAT TRIPLE "D" JOINTS.
SO I'M IN AN AREA
CALLED SOUTH MAIN
RIGHT BY CENTRAL STATION
TO CHECK OUT
A LITTLE HOLE-IN-THE-WALL JOINT
CALLED RIZZO'S DINER.
(man) WHEN YOU WALK IN
OFF THE STREETS,
YOU REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO EXPECT.
(man) LOBSTER PRONTO PUP UP.
MICHAEL IS A WELL-KNOWN CHEF
AROUND THIS CITY.
WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING HIM
AROUND MEMPHIS
FROM, UM, RESTAURANT
TO RESTAURANT.
I STALKED MICHAEL PATRICK
THE CHEF. HE IS OUR FAVORITE.
YOU MEAN "RIZZO"?
A NICKNAME THAT FOLLOWED
MICHAEL PATRICK
ALL THE WAY
FROM HIS HOMETOWN OF CLEVELAND.
IT'S NICE TO FOLLOW HIM HERE
TO WHERE WE CAN SHARE
IN A LITTLE PIECE OF HIS DREAM.
WHICH INVOLVED OPENING A JOINT
WITH HIS NAME ON IT IN 2011.
(Michael) ORDER UP.
WE'RE A CASUAL UPSCALE DINER.
I TAKE SOME TRADITIONAL
SOUTHERN FOOD
AND KIND OF JAZZ IT UP
WITH A CHEF'S INTERPRETATION.
PUT 'EM BOTH UP, PLEASE,
LIKE THIS.
JAZZ HANDS.
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S JAZZING IT UP.
BUT IT'S ALL ROCK 'N' ROLL
WITH BURGERS STRAIGHT
FROM THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
(Michael) BURGER G.E.
ORDERED UP.
THIS IS
THE G.E. PATTERSON BURGER,
WHICH IS NAMED
AFTER THE STREET.
SCALLOPS WITH GRITS
THAT'S A TWIST
ON KIND OF A NEW ORLEANS
TRADITIONAL SHRIMP AND GRITS.
OR HIS RENDITION
OF THIS DOWN-HOME CLASSIC.
MEAT LOAF'S UP.
LIKE YOUR MOM'S MEAT LOAF
WITH A LITTLE KICK.
(woman) THIS CHORIZO
IN THIS MEAT LOAF--GOOD.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL?
DID IT MAKE YOUR HAIR STAND UP?
MM-HMM.
AND I LOVE HIS, UH,
TOMATO GRAVY--IT'S KILLER.
CHORIZO MEAT LOAF--
AND THIS IS MEXICAN CHORIZO.
GREAT FLAVOR IN IT.
WELL, GET IT GOING.
WELL, I WANT TO START
SAUTéING THE VEGGIES FIRST.
GONNA ADD A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL TO OUR SKILLET,
ADD A LITTLE GARLIC,
THE POBLANO.
WE'RE NOT GOING
SUPER SPICY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA
ADD ONION.
WE'RE GONNA LET 'EM COOK
FOR A COUPLE SECONDS,
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA DEGLAZE
WITH THE WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
AND I'M GONNA DEGLAZE
WITH A LITTLE OF OUR
HOUSE-MADE BARBECUE SAUCE--
SWEETEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
GOT IT.
PULL IT OFF.
LET IT COOL DOWN.
NEXT UP?
WE'LL START WITH
80/20 GROUND BEEF,
BLACK ANGUS--CLAYBROOK FARMS,
LOCALLY RAISED.
LOVE. THE FARM-TO-TABLE ATTITUDE
IN THIS TOWN IS OUTRAGEOUS.
ADD OUR CHORIZO
AND A LITTLE MORE GARLIC.
OKAY.
CREOLE MUSTARD,
AND THE VEGGIES WE COOKED OFF
EARLIER--WE'RE GONNA ADD THEM.
A COUPLE EGGS, AND THAT'S IT
FOR THE WET INGREDIENTS.
PANKO BREADCRUMBS.
MY FAVORITE.
JAPANESE FINE--
YEAH, I LOVE IT.
OKAY.
YOU NEED A LITTLE
SALT AND PEPPER?
YEAH, YOU WANT
TO HOOK ME UP?
ABSOLUTELY. READY?
THANK YOU. YES.
I'M JUST GONNA GET IN HERE
AND MIX THIS UP.
THE SAME THING
ON THE MEATBALL THEORY--
DON'T WANT
TO MIX IT TOO MUCH.
SHAPE THE MEAT LOAF
FOR ME.
LOG O' MEAT.
I'M GONNA ROLL 'EM
IN SOME FOIL.
AS IN SUCH.
UH-HUH.
PAT IT A LITTLE BIT,
AND I'M GONNA ROLL.
THEY GO ONTO THE SHEET TRAY
INTO THE OVEN, 275
FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES?
YEAH, 45 TO AN HOUR.
CAN I GET A LITTLE, UH,
JOHN CANDY BEFORE WE GO?
ALL RIGHT.
THERE YOU GO.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO THE OVEN.
NOW WE'RE MAKING
THE GREEN TOMATO GRAVY.
YEAH.
TURN THIS BAD BOY ON.
GREEN TOMATOES.
OKAY.
GONNA ADD MY WINE,
SOME SHALLOTS, SOME ROSEMARY.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME CHICKEN STOCK.
BRING THAT UP TO A BOIL
AND LET IT REDUCE A SEC,
ALMOST DRY.
YEAH. NOW WE'RE REDUCED DOWN.
NOW THE CRèME.
WE'LL LET THE CRèME REDUCE
BY HALF. TOMATOES COOK DOWN.
SOME OF THOSE NATURAL
HEART FLAVORS
ARE DANCING AROUND
IN THERE.
HOW ARE THEY DANCING?
LIKE THIS--
WITH JAZZ HANDS, MAN.
(laughs) NICE.
IT'S A DINNER SHOW.
SO NOW THAT
THE REDUCTION IS FINISHED,
REMOVE THE ROSEMARY.
AND HOW MUCH BUTTER?
A WHOPPING POUND
OF BUTTER TO THIS.
GET IT GOING. WE'RE GONNA
START ADDING THE BUTTER IN.
THIS LOOKS AWESOME.
SOME SALT AND PEPPER,
AND THAT'LL FINISH IT OFF.
THE GREEN TOMATO GRAVY'S DONE,
MEAT LOAF'S OUT.
SEAR THIS, GET A NICE
LITTLE CRISPNESS TO IT.
ADD A LITTLE OIL TO THE SKILLET.
I'M GONNA DROP IT IN.
GET THAT NICE CRUSTY SEAR
I LIKE TO SEE IN MY MEAT LOAF.
I'M GONNA SAUTé SOME FRESH
VEGETABLES TO GO ALONG WITH IT.
SNAP PEAS,
CHERRY TOMATOES.
NOW FLIP
THIS BAD BOY OVER.
SALT AND PEPPER,
AND I FINISH THIS IN THE OVEN.
ADD THESE PEAS
AND TOMATOES ON HERE.
GRAB THE MEAT LOAF OUT.
I'LL LADLE SOME OF THIS
GREEN TOMATO GRAVY OVER IT.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT ACID IN THERE,
SO IT'S NOT JUST
CREAMY GRAVY ALL THE WAY.
YEAH.
MMM.
THAT CHORIZO IN THERE HAS ITS
DISTINCT FLAVOR THAT IT ADDS.
THEN YOU GET A COMPLETELY
BLINDSIDE SHOT
FROM THIS
GREEN TOMATO GRAVY.
MMM.
MMM, THAT GREEN TOMATO
GRAVY'S NUTS.
THIS IS COMFORT
WITH A TWIST.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU BUILD IT,
AND THEY WILL COME.
NICE JOB. DIFFERENT MOVIE,
BUT YOU GET THE POINT.
MEAT LOAF'S UP.
IT'S GOT ALL KINDS
OF FLAVORS IN IT.
IT'S NOT LIKE JUST HAVING
A HAMBURGER, YOU KNOW?
IT'S AMAZING, AND I'M
ADDICTED TO IT NOW.
REALLY?
SO I COME AT LEAST
ONCE A WEEK, YEAH.
(Guy) YOU'VE SEEN
THIS NEIGHBORHOOD
GO THROUGH
QUITE A BIT, HUH?
A LOT.
I MEAN, THIS HAS BEEN
A WHOLE TURNAROUND.
IT'S JUST WONDERFUL
WHAT'S HAPPENING IN SOUTH MAIN.
THE PERFECT PLACE FOR RIZZO
TO DO A LITTLE
REINVENTION HIMSELF.
(Michael) GOT ICE CREAM
ON THE FRENCH TOAST.
SMOKED DUCK TAMALE PIE.
LOBSTER PRONTO PUP.
IT'S SORT OF LIKE
HEALTHY CARNIVAL FOOD.
LOBSTER PRONTO PUP.
LOBSTER PRONTO PUPS?
YEAH. I WANTED TO TAKE
THE PRONTO PUP AND JAZZ IT UP,
AS I SAID BEFORE.
JAZZ IT UP.
AND, UH...
WOW, THIS IS S A FULL
FLOOR SHOW, ISN'T IT?
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH SOME FLOUR, THE SUGAR.
WE GOT DRY MUSTARD.
SALT AND PEPPER,
OUR CORNSTARCH,
AN EGG, AND WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR MILK,
AND WE HAVE SOME
LEMON-LIME SODA.
FOR THE CARBONATION,
THE AIRINESS.
RIGHT, SO WE'RE
AIRING THIS OUT.
WE WANT TO SWEETEN IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY.
WHISK ALL THIS TOGETHER,
AND THERE'S OUR BATTER.
NICE AND CREAMY.
YEAH.
TEMPURA, PANCAKE BATTER-ISH
CONSISTENCY.
OUR NEXT STEP WOULD BE
TO DO OUR LOBSTER MEAT.
FIVE OF 'EM.
OKAY, LITTLE
SLIPPER LOBSTERS.
THERE YOU GO--ONE, TWO,
THREE, FOUR, FIVE.
ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
TAKE THIS, SPLIT IT ALL
THE WAY DOWN, REMOVE THE MEAT.
IT CURLS UP PRETTY GOOD
WHEN IT--WHEN IT BLANCHES.
YOU BLANCHE
THE MEAT FIRST?
SO THEY'RE GONNA BE
A LITTLE PARCOOKED.
NOW WE'VE GOT
OUR BOILING WATER HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA SEASON
THE WATER A LITTLE BIT.
A LITTLE LEMON.
SALT AND PEPPER,
YOU WANT?
YES, SIR.
WE'LL ADD THE MEAT.
NOW DROP 'EM IN.
THIS IS JUST GONNA GO
HOT AND FAST.
ALL IT NEEDS IS ABOUT
TWO TO THREE MINUTES.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
REMOVE THE LOBSTER.
KIND OF LIKE
BOBBING FOR APPLES.
ALL RIGHT.
AND THEN ICE BATH.
GONNA REST IN HERE, JUST
ABSORB SOME OF THAT MOISTURE.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA SKEWER
THIS MEAT, RUN IT THROUGH HERE.
I WANT TO GET THROUGH THE MIDDLE
OF IT TO GET IT NICE AND TIGHT.
THIS ISN'T ANY JOKE HERE.
THIS IS THE REAL DEAL.
I MEAN, YOU'RE
LOADING IT UP.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA BATTER
THE LOBSTER PRONTO PUP TO FRY.
NICE LITTLE COATING.
OHH, THAT'S GOOD.
WHEN THEY'RE FLOATING,
I GIVE 'EM ANOTHER, YOU KNOW,
30, 40 SECONDS.
ALL YOU REALLY
HAVE TO WAIT FOR ON THIS
IS FOR THAT BATTER
TO BROWN UP ON THE OUTSIDE,
BECAUSE THAT SLIPPER LOBSTER
IS COOKED ALL THE WAY THROUGH.
YES.
HOW ARE WE LOOKING?
WE'RE LOOKING THERE.
A LOBSTER CORNDOG.
ONLY IN MEMPHIS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE ARUGULA,
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
SALT AND PEPPER.
LAY THESE ON,
A LITTLE CROSS.
THEN DRIZZLE A LITTLE
CREOLE MUSTARD AIOLI.
OKAY.
WOW, THAT'S HOT.
OH, LOOK AT THIS.
MOMMY.
THAT WAS HOT.
WOW, THE LOBSTER'S
SUPER TENDER.
IT'S JUST DELICATE.
MMM.
I MEAN, THIS ISN'T EVEN
TEMPURA BATTER TENDER.
THIS IS EVEN LIGHTER
THAN THAT.
AND THERE'S A LITTLE BIT
OF SWEETNESS TO IT,
BUT THEN YOU BALANCE IT OUT
WITH THE ACIDITY,
YOU KNOW, OF THAT
CREOLE MUSTARD. MMM.
GOOD STUFF?
THAT IS
LOBSTER CORNDOG 101.
NICELY DONE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
(woman) IT IS LIKE
HEAVEN ON A STICK.
THE LOBSTER'S SO SWEET.
IT'S JUST DELICIOUS.
EVERYTHING'S JUST REALLY GOOD.
HE CARES ABOUT HIS INGREDIENTS,
AND IT COMES THROUGH
IN HIS PRODUCT.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW
HIS NAME WAS RIZZO?
NO, I ALWAYS CALLED HIM
MICHAEL PATRICK.
"MICHAEL P."
MICHAEL PATRICK?
YES, SIR.
DUDE, I LOVED YOU IN RIVERDANCE.
YOU WERE THE BOMB.
♪♪
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND.
THIS IS THE REAL-DEAL
LOCALS JOINT.
THAT'S HIDING A TRUE TALENT...
YOU GAVE UP THAT SMALL
MUSIC STINT YOU HAD THERE,
JON MAYER, FOR A WHILE.
WELL, JENNIFER ANISTON
DROPPED ME.
AND SOME KILLER BARBECUE.
OH, YOU GUYS
ARE RUNNING THE TAPE?
♪♪
I'M HERE IN ANNAPOLIS, MARYLAND,
ON CHESTER AVENUE,
RIGHT OVER BY BACK CREEK,
AND THAT'S WHERE THEY USED
TO LOAD IN THE OYSTER BOATS
WHO WOULD GO OUT
TO THE OYSTER BEDS.
NOW BACK IN THE '30s,
THIS GUY NAMED GEORGE DAVIS
OPENS UP THIS LITTLE
GROCERY STORE.
HE LATER TURNS THE GROCERY STORE
INTO KIND OF A LOUNGE
FOR THE LOCALS, AND THEN
ADDS A RESTAURANT TO IT,
AND IT CONTINUES ON
THAT WAY TODAY.
THIS IS THE REAL-DEAL
LOCALS JOINT.
THIS IS DAVIS' PUB.
IT IS CLASSIC PUB FOOD.
MMM.
AWESOME BURGERS,
GOOD FRIES.
THE STEAMED SHRIMP
IS GREAT.
REALLY?
(laughs) YOU DON'T EAT 'EM,
YOU JUST KISS 'EM?
I DO.
CRAB CAKE COMING OVER--HOT.
THE FOOD SPEAKS FOR ITSELF.
THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE DAVIS'.
NO PLACE.
OR "D. PUB,"
AS WE CALL IT.
THE D. PUB,
IF YOU'RE ON THE IN.
AND BEING ON THE IN
IS EXACTLY HOW KIYOMI ENDO
ENDED UP OWNING THE JOINT.
THE FELLOW WHO OWNED IT
BEFORE MYSELF
JUST TOLD ME IF I STARTED
WORKING FOR HIM
AND HELPED HIM RUN THE PLACE,
HE'D SELL ME THE BUSINESS
UNDER THE CONDITION THAT IF
YOU ARE EVER TO SELL IT AGAIN,
YOU SELL IT
TO SOMEONE ELSE.
SO PICK A GUY IN THE KITCHEN,
PICK ONE OF THE BARTENDERS,
SELL IT TO THEM.
SO THE NEXT OWNER COULD END UP
BEING LONG-TIME CHEF
JON MAYER.
CRAB DIP.
WELL, I'VE BEEN HERE
ABOUT A DECADE--11 YEARS.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
SO YOU GAVE UP THAT SMALL
MUSIC STINT YOU HAD THERE,
JON MAYER, FOR A WHILE.
WELL, JENNIFER ANISTON
DROPPED ME,
AND I HAD TO FIND
SOMETHING ELSE TO DO.
AND THAT CHANGED IT ALL.
LUCKY FOR HIM,
IT'S WORKED OUT...
ALL RIGHT, YOU GOT A PLATE READY
FOR THE BARBECUE?
AND HE'S MADE A CAREER SERVING
FOOD THAT THE PUB'S FAMOUS FOR,
LIKE TWISTING UP THE FRESHEST
MARYLAND SEAFOOD...
CRAP PRETZEL.
WHAT MAKES IT SO GOOD?
THE CHEESE
AND THE REAL CRAB.
OR DAILY SPECIALS THAT ARE
ALL OVER THE MAP.
I GET A TEXT THAT THE PORK
BURRITO IS UP ON THE MENU.
ONE WORD TEXT--"BURRITO."
(man) THIS IS THE CHIPOTLE
HABANERO BARBECUE SANDWICH.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
LET'S GO.
GOT A BOSTON
PORK BUTT THERE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE THAT AND WE'RE
GONNA MAKE A RUB FOR IT.
AND THIS IS ALL
GOING TOGETHER FOR...
THE CHIPOTLE HABANERO
BARBECUE SANDWICH.
BROWN SUGAR, SALT,
CHILI POWDER,
WE GOT SOME ONION POWDER,
OLD BAY SEASONING,
PAPRIKA,
BLACK PEPPER, CUMIN,
CAYENNE,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
MIX THAT UP REAL NICE.
NOW WE'RE JUST GONNA
LOVINGLY MASSAGE THIS
INTO THE TOP OF THE MEAT.
DID YOU HAVE TO SAY
"LOVINGLY"?
IT DOESN'T GO TOGETHER
REAL WELL, DOES IT?
YOU ARE GETTING INTIMATE
WITH YOUR FOOD.
SO YOU SCORE IT.
LET THAT SEASONING
GET PAST THAT FAT CAP.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT IN THE
WALK-IN, LET IT SIT OVERNIGHT.
ARE WE THROWING THIS
IN THE OVEN?
ARE WE GOING
TO THE SMOKER?
WE'RE GONNA THROW THAT
IN A SMOKER OUT BACK.
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE IT
FOR ABOUT 8 HOURS AT 225.
IT'S GONNA FALL
RIGHT OFF THE BONE.
SHRED IT UP REAL WELL. JUST PUT
IT ON THE BUN RIGHT HERE.
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR HOMEMADE
BARBECUE SAUCE,
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
OUR COLESLAW.
IT'S GONNA GIVE A NICE TANG.
GIVE IT A TRY.
♪ HERE WE GO ♪
PORK'S JUICY, TENDER.
OH, YOU GUYS
ARE RUNNING TAPE?
IT'S GOT A NICE
LITTLE TANG TO IT.
NOT TOO HOT.
IT'S ON THE THINNER,
MORE VINEGARY SIDE
OF THE BARBECUE SAUCE,
WHICH I ENJOY WITH PORK.
UH-HUH.
NICE KEISER ROLL,
GRILLED BOTH SIDES--VERY KEY--
AND A GOOD LITTLE
SUPPORTING SLAW.
IF THIS IS YOUR OFFERINGS
IN THE BARBECUE WORLD,
YOU'RE DOING WELL.
WELL, THANK YOU.
(woman) CHIPOTLE PORK
BARBECUE.
YOU'RE NOT PLAYING, YOU KNOW,
CULINARY ROULETTE HERE.
(both) NO.
YOU'RE GONNA GET
SOMETHING YOU ENJOY.
(man) YOU WANT A REAL TASTE
OF THE PERSONALITY
AND THE FLAVOR OF ANNAPOLIS,
COME TO DAVIS' PUB.
(Kiyomi) OUR SLOGAN
OUT FRONT IS, UM,
"WHERE THERE ARE
NO STRANGERS,
ONLY FRIENDS
YOU HAVEN'T MET YET."
THERE ARE NO STRANGERS,
JUST A LOT OF STRANGE PEOPLE.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
GIVE ME SOME MORE
"SCARFACE."
(imitating Tony Montana)
TELL ME WHAT TO SAY,
WHAT TO DO.
(laughter)