HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
MMM.
WE'RE MEETING UP WITH SOME
HARD-CORE HANDCRAFTERS.
DO YOU WANT TO TRY
SOME APPETIZERS?
I KNOW WHERE
THEY CAME FROM.
IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE...
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING NOW?
THE FARM-TO-TABLE MAESTRO...
YOU'LL NEVER LEAVE HERE AND GO
HOME AND HAVE A BOWL OF CEREAL.
CRANKING OUT
CLASSIC COMFORT...
THAT'S AN ADULT
SLOPPY JOE.
WITH CRAZY ATTENTION
TO DETAIL.
HE KNOWS EVERYTHING INCLUDING
THE SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBER
AND SHOE SIZE OF THE PEOPLE
THAT HE BUYS THINGS FROM.
AND IN EAST PROVIDENCE,
RHODE ISLAND...
GOTTA WORK THAT
THROTTLE, EASY.
THE REAL-DEAL ITALIAN DELI...
OH, YOU GUYS
ARE CLASSIC.
TAKING THE CHARMS OF MILAN...
YOU KNOW HOW COOL
YOU ARE
WHEN YOU HAVE A PLACE
CALLED THE PASTA ROOM?
EVERY SINGLE STEP OF THE WAY.
I'M GONNA SO HAVE
TO PUSH THE CAR
ALL THE WAY BACK TO CALIFORNIA
JUST TO WORK THIS OFF.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
WHEN YOU CRUISE ABOUT
20 MINUTES EAST
OUTSIDE OF DOWNTOWN MEMPHIS,
HERE ON POPLAR AVENUE,
IT PUTS YOU IN
THE UNIVERSITY OF MEMPHIS AREA,
WHERE THERE'S A JOINT THAT'S
DOING SOMETHING I TOTALLY DIG.
THAT'S FARM-TO-TABLE.
THIS IS THE ELEGANT FARMER.
POT ROAST IN THE WINDOW.
EVERYTHING HERE IS, LIKE,
SO WHOLESOME. JUST SO GOOD.
WE GOT A SALMON "BURGER"
AND A TOSTADA.
YOU'RE GONNA EAT HEALTHY HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA EAT LOCAL.
YOUR HAM TARTINE.
IT'S RIGHT OFF THE FARM.
AND MAC GOES TO THE FARMERS'
MARKET AND PICKS IT OUT HIMSELF.
THAT'S CHEF AND OWNER
MAC EDWARDS...
I NEED TO GET SOME
POTATOES TODAY.
A CALI NATIVE
WHO'S BEEN SERVING UP
FRESH SEASONAL
COMFORT FOOD SINCE 2011.
I LOOK THE PERSON
IN THE EYE
THAT ACTUALLY GROWS THE FOOD,
WHICH IS REALLY COOL.
WHAT, LIKE I.D.
SCANNER OR SOMETHING?
ALMOST, YEAH, YEAH.
YOU GET RIGHT UP
IN THAT--
RETINA SCANNING,
YEAH.
RIGHT UP LIKE THAT.
THAT'S WEIRD.
YEAH, DO YOU REALLY
GROW THIS FOOD? YEAH.
CATFISH.
(woman) AND THE CATFISH HAS
A GREAT FLAVOR TO IT.
YOU'VE GOT THE MAC 'N CHEESE
AND THE GREENS
AND THE TOMATO SAUCE ALL ON
ONE PLATE. IT'S REALLY GOOD.
SO WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE FIRST?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SMOKED TOMATO BROTH
FOR THE PAN-SEARED
OVEN-ROASTED CATFISH.
OKAY.
QUALITY--
HIGH QUALITY SMOKER, YEAH.
BANJO SMOKER.
AND YOU SEE IT'S BEEN USED
A COUPLE OF TIMES.
THOSE ARE HICKORY CHIPS.
THE TOMATOES.
THESE ARE FROM MICMAK FARMS
IN BATESVILLE, ARKANSAS.
ABOUT TEN CLOVES OF GARLIC,
ONE LARGE CHOPPED ONION.
THIS IS, AS WE SAY IN THE SOUTH,
TINFOIL. NOT FOIL, TINFOIL.
TINFOIL.
WHY NOT HAVE A SMOKER?
HAVE YOU SEEN HOW SMALL
MY KITCHEN IS?
I THOUGHT, LIKE, IN MEMPHIS,
EVERYBODY HAD A SMOKER,
IT'S LIKE TWO CARS IN
EVERY GARAGE, KIND OF THING.
I HAVE ONE IN THE BATHROOM
AT HOME, YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT I MEANT.
YEAH, EXACTLY, YEAH.
START THE SMOKE?
YEAH. IT'S GONNA GO
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
SO AFTER ABOUT
A HALF AN HOUR...
THAT SOUNDED VERY
MISTER ROGERS-ISH.
I'M BIG ON
THE SWEATER VEST.
WHEN I'M NOT WEARING
THE CHEF JACKET...
REALLY?
THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE ROCKIN'?
I'M SPORTING
THE SWEATER VEST, YEAH.
LET'S GO VISIT
MISTER POSTMAN.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
THAT'S OUR GARLIC,
OUR TOMATO, AND OUR ONION.
NOW THE SPARKLING RIVER PEPPER
COMPANY HOT SAUCE, TOMATO PASTE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA GIVE THIS
A GOOD MIX WITH A BURR MIXER.
ARE WE GONNA STRAIN THIS,
OR ARE WE GOING A LA CHUNK-AY?
YEAH, NO,
WE'RE GONNA STRAIN IT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING NOW?
BEATING IT TO DEATH.
THERE WE GO.
WE GOT SAUCE.
AND YOU THINK
YOU'RE THIN ENOUGH?
I THINK SO.
ONCE WE HEAT IT UP--
OH, THAT'S NICE.
NICE LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE TO IT,
BUT YOU STILL GET THE TOMATOES,
STILL GET THE ONIONS,
STILL GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE GARLIC. MMM.
WE'RE JUST GONNA HEAT
THAT THROUGH AND GO WITH IT.
OKAY.
WE'RE MAKING THE BRAISED GREENS
THAT GOES WITH THE CATFISH.
I'M A GREEN EATING MACHINE.
FIRE IT UP.
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL,
ONIONS,
GARLIC, BROWN SUGAR,
LITTLE CIDER VINEGAR.
GET YOUR SWEET AND SOUR THERE
WITH YOUR CARAMELIZED ONIONS.
THEN AFTER ABOUT 20 MINUTES,
WE START ADDING THE GREENS
AND START SWEATING 'EM DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SMOKED MARCONI PEPPERS.
THOSE ARE FROM
ARKANSAS...
OF COURSE THEY ARE.
THEY'RE FROM THE
SPARKLING RIVER PEPPER COMPANY.
THE SPARKLING RIVER
PEPPER COMPANY.
GET A WHIFF OF THAT.
TRY SOME OF THIS.
HMM, WHAT DO YOU
THINK?
SO THE GREENS ARE DONE.
CATFISH TIME.
CATFISH.
EARL LAKE,
DUNDEE, MISSISSIPPI.
THERE YOU GO.
FIRST IS A LITTLE
OLIVE OIL,
SPOONFUL OF BUTTER TO GET
THAT GOOD CARAMELIZATION.
OKAY. SALT AND PEPPER.
SALT AND PEPPER.
HERE'S OUR SAFETY TIP--PUT IT
IN THE PAN GOING AWAY FROM YOU.
I'VE DONE THAT.
"HERE'S OUR SAFETY TIP."
GET A HARD SEAR ON THAT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA FLIP IT,
FINISH IN THE OVEN.
TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
OW.
THAT'S HOT IN THERE,
AIN'T IT?
YEAH, YOU KNOW?
THEY DON'T CALL IT
THE REFRIGERATOR, YOU KNOW?
A LITTLE SMOKED TOMATO BROTH.
A LITTLE MAC 'N CHEESE HERE.
SO ELEGANT FARMER DOESN'T DO
THOSE LITTLE ELEGANT PORTIONS.
NO, YOU'LL NEVER
LEAVE HERE AND GO HOME
AND HAVE A BOWL
OF CEREAL, EVER.
ESPECIALLY ME,
'CAUSE HOME'S IN CALIFORNIA.
YEAH, EXACTLY, THAT'S
A LONG WAY FOR YOU TO GO.
SO THIS IS THE GREENS THAT WE
CUT THE PEPPERS UP IN, YOU KNOW.
YEP.
OH, MY GOSH, BROTHER.
YOU GET THAT LITTLE BIT OF THE
SMOKE COMING FROM THE TOMATOES,
BUT IT'S NOT LIKE YOU
SMOKED THE WHOLE FISH,
SO THE FISH STILL HAS
ITS TRUE BALANCED FLAVOR.
YOU TASTE THE FRESHNESS,
SUPER TENDER.
I WOULD BE SURPRISED IF
YOU TOLD ME THERE WASN'T FLOUR
ON THAT FISH,
GREAT CRUST ON THAT.
AND THEN THE COLLARD GREENS,
YOU'VE GOT ABOUT AN HOUR ON 'EM,
A LITTLE SUGAR, THE GARLIC,
AND THE ONIONS.
AND THE SMOKED PEPPER.
THAT LITTLE KICK
OF THAT PEPPER--
NOT THE HEAT, BUT THAT
ROASTED, SMOKED DEPTH,
SERIOUSLY OUTSTANDING.
THANK YOU.
THANKS, BUDDY.
DON'T TOUCH IT.
CATFISH IN THE WINDOW.
YOUR CATFISH.
IT'S ALWAYS PREPARED BETTER
THAN ANYBODY ELSE COULD DO IT,
AND THAT'S WHAT WE LOVE
ABOUT MAC.
AND HIS DEDICATION RUNS DEEP.
ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL,
ORDER UP.
COME ON, THIS DUDE
NOT ONLY SHOPS
THE MEMPHIS FARMERS MARKET...
EIGHT BUNCHES
OF KALE, PLEASE.
HE'S A FOUNDING
BOARD MEMBER.
THIS IS
OUR SEVENTH SEASON.
REALLY?
YEAH.
SO HE DOESN'T TRAVEL FAR TO
SOURCE HIS COUNTRY FRIED STEAK,
PORK CHOP, AND THIS
CHILDHOOD FAVORITE--
THE SLOPPY JOE.
(Mac) SLOPPY JOE IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S A SLOPPY SLOPPY JOE.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
SLOPPY JOE.
I'M A BIG
SLOPPY JOE FAN.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
THE VEGETABLES, OLIVE OIL.
WE GOT CARROT.
CARROT, CELERY,
ONION.
A LITTLE SALT
TO GET 'EM SWEATING OUT.
NUTMEG, SOME CLOVE,
CAYENNE,
GARLIC,
AND WE'RE GONNA
COOK THAT DOWN.
NOW WE'RE GONNA START
THE GROUND BEEF.
THIS IS 80-20 ANGUS BEEF.
LEAVE IT KIND OF CHUNKY.
OKAY.
ALL THE GROUND BEEF
AND THE FAT AND JUICES,
MIXED IN WITH
THE VEGETABLES.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BROWN SUGAR,
KETCHUP,
AND SOME TOMATO PASTE,
CIDER VINEGAR,
WORCESTERSHIRE.
SO HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA COOK DOWN THEN?
THIS IS GONNA GO ABOUT A HALF
AN HOUR, OR A LITTLE LESS--
20, 30 MINUTES.
IT'LL BREAK DOWN
JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE...
YEAH.
SOFTEN UP THE VEGGIES.
TASTE THAT.
MMM.
A LITTLE TOASTED
BAKERY BUN HERE.
SO THIS ISN'T
SUPERHEAVY TOMATO BASED.
THERE IS TOMATO IN IT,
BUT YOU GET
MORE OF THE SPICES.
BUT THE MEAT'S GOT
REAL GOOD MOUTHFEEL TO IT.
HAVING THAT LITTLE
BIT THICKER GRIND,
I THINK REALLY--
REALLY HELPS IT.
NICE BUN WORKING AS A VESSEL
TO SHOVE IT IN YOUR MOUTH.
THERE YOU GO.
IT'S BIG FLAVOR.
THAT'S AN ADULT SLOPPY JOE.
YEAH, IT IS.
OUTSTANDING.
NICE JOB. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT.
(man) SLOPPY JOE.
HAVING THE SLOPPY JOE.
IT'S DELICIOUS,
UNCTUOUS AND JUST TASTES
REALLY GOOD.
YOU CAN'T DO ANYTHING ELSE
TO ME. THERE'S NO WAY.
DUCK AND COVER.
THE VIETNAMESE
BANH YOU, BANH MI SANDWICH.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE HANGING
OUT AT THE ELEGANT FARMER
IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE,
WITH A CRAZY GUY.
WE'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
THE DUDE IS FROM
OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA,
COMES OUT HERE
TO MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE,
TO OPEN UP A FARM-TO-TABLE
RESTAURANT, THE ELEGANT FARMER,
AND YOU TAKE IT--
MAKE WHAT EVERYBODY LOVES,
JUST DO IT WITH YOUR ECLECTIC
FARM-TO-TABLE SPIN.
A LOT OF LOVE, LOT OF FLAVOR.
YEAH, JUST KEEP IT SIMPLE, YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GOING TO HAVE ANOTHER
ALL-AMERICAN FAVORITE, THE...
THE VIETNAMESE
BANH YOU, BANH MI SANDWICH.
ALL RIGHT,
SO GET US STARTED.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'VE GOT
A B.R.T.--
A BONED AND ROLLED
AND TIED HAM.
ROLLED, TIED, YEP.
THIS IS NEWMAN FARMS
IN MYRTLE, MISSOURI.
THE PORK IS SO DARN GOOD.
OH, BY THE WAY,
LET ME ALSO REMIND YOU,
HE KNOWS EVERYTHING INCLUDING
THE SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBER
AND SHOE SIZE OF THE PEOPLE
THAT HE BUYS THINGS FROM.
'CAUSE HE DOES
A, UH, RETINA SCAN.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE GOT DRIED
HERBS. WE GOT OREGANO,
THEN TARRAGON.
YOU GONNA HIT
THE THYME IN THERE?
THYME.
OR THE TH-YME?
TH-YME, AS WE SAY, YEAH.
BASIL.
AND ROSEMARY.
VERY NICE.
SALT AND PEPPER.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
RUB IT IN, HIT IT WITH
A LITTLE OLIVE OIL HERE.
OKAY, SO BROWN IT
ON BOTH SIDES.
LET THAT GO,
BROWN BOTH SIDES.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE
GONNA ADD THE VEGETABLES--
CARROTS, CELERY,
CHOPPED ONION,
GARLIC CLOVES,
CUP OF WHITE WINE,
AND WATER TO COVER
ABOUT TWO-THIRDS OF THE PORK.
SEAL IT UP REALLY GOOD
WITH FOIL,
AND PUT IT IN THE OVEN
AT 250 ALL NIGHT.
OKAY. SO IT'S OUT.
IT'S COOL.
NOW WHAT HAPPENS?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE PICKLED VEGETABLES
THAT GO ON
THE BANH MI SANDWICH.
OKAY.
SO WE'VE GOT DAIKON,
CUCUMBER.
WE HAVE POBLANO CHILIES,
CARROT, AND THEN RED ONION.
THIS IS RICE WINE VINEGAR,
OLIVE OIL, AND GARLIC.
AND WHILE IT'S STILL WARM, WE
TOSS THAT OVER THE VEGETABLES.
FIVE, SIX MINUTES,
IT'S READY TO GO.
ABOUT 4 OUNCES.
WE'RE GONNA GO PUT THIS
ON THE GRILL FOR A MINUTE.
WARM THIS THROUGH
A LITTLE BIT.
THIS IS FISH SAUCE,
SOY SAUCE, AND WATER.
OKAY.
THIS IS OUR SESAME AIOLI
WE MAKE FROM SCRATCH, FROM HERE.
A LITTLE PORK ON THERE,
SOME OF THE VEGETABLE,
YOU GET THAT VINEGAR
IN THERE.
YOU GET THE SEASONED PORK.
THAT'S BABY CILANTRO.
FROM WOODSON RIDGE
DOWN IN OXFORD, MISSISSIPPI.
THERE YOU GO.
THE ROLL SEEMS TO BE
TO SPEC.
OH, YEAH,
IT'S A SOUS-MARIN.
SOUS-MARIN?
S-O-U-S, YEAH.
ONE OF THOSE FRENCH WORDS.
MMM. IF YOU'RE GONNA GET THE
CHANCE TO EAT A PORK SANDWICH,
TREAT IT WITH RESPECT,
DON'T HAVE TO OVER SEASON IT,
DON'T HAVE TO BRINE,
DON'T HAVE TO PUMP IT.
THEN YOU DO REALLY NICE
VEGETABLES,
SUPER-THINLY SLICED.
IT'S NOT TOO MUCH DRESSING.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
AN ORCHESTRA OF FLAVORS.
THE COMPLEXITIES OF THE FLAVORS
AND THE TEXTURES ARE KEY.
IT'S A NICE THIN ROLL
WITH A GREAT CRUST.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
(man)
BANH YOU, BANH MI PORK.
THE KIND OF SAVORY FLAVORS
OF THE PORK AND THE CILANTRO
WORKING TOGETHER--IT'S JUST
ONE OF MY FAVORITES HERE.
YOU KNOW HOW
FARM-TO-TABLE IT IS
BECAUSE OF THE RANTING
AND RAVING BY THE CRAZY GUY.
DOES HE EVER COME OUT TO
YOUR TABLE AND TALK TO YOU?
HE DOES.
HE TOLD ME THE SHOE SIZE OF
THE GUY THAT MADE THE DUCK EGG.
YEAH, AWKWARD.
COME DOWN, 'CAUSE HE'LL
BE AT YOUR TABLE--
DO YOU WANT TO TRY SOME
APPETIZERS?
I KNOW WHERE
THEY CAME FROM.
UP NEXT...
JACKPOT.
WE'RE HEADED TO EAST
PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND...
PLACE IS OFF THE HOOK.
FOR A FAMILY ITALIAN DELI...
YEAH.
TAKING AUTHENTIC
TO THE ABSOLUTE EXTREME.
I WANT ONE
FOR CHRISTMAS.
OH, I GOT A GREAT ONE FOR YOU--
TWO BROTHER-IN-LAWS
FROM BRISTOL, RHODE ISLAND.
SEE, THEY'RE IN THE COMPUTER
BUSINESS TOGETHER,
WELL, TIMES ARE CHANGING
AND THINGS ARE TOUGH,
SO THEY DECIDE, HEY, WE'LL GET
INTO THE ITALIAN DELI BUSINESS.
NOW HERE IN EAST PROVIDENCE,
THERE'S SOME TOUGH COMPETITION.
BUT WORD ON THE STREET IS,
THESE DUDES ARE KILLING IT.
THIS IS ITALIAN CORNER.
♪♪
(man) MORTADELLA
WITH THE WORKS.
EVERYTHING IS HOMEMADE.
(woman) CHICKEN PICCATA.
YOU CAN TELL
THE PASSION IS THERE.
IT COMES OUT IN THE FOOD.
THAT'S WHAT YOU GET WHEN
THE TWO CATS RUNNING THE JOINT
WERE BORN AND RAISED
IN MILAN.
HI, HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
THAT'D BE OWNER OSVALDO PIRRO
AND HIS BROTHER-IN-LAW
AND CHEF MASSIMO DELLOLIO.
HOW ARE YOU?
(woman) GOOD, THANKS.
SINCE '05, THEY'VE BEEN
CELEBRATING THEIR ROOTS
WITH A DELI COUNTER SERVING UP
SCRATCH-MADE ITALIAN
AND A MARKET THAT'D BE
RIGHT AT HOME IN ROME.
THIS IS IT, MAN.
THIS IS DISNEYLAND.
ALL THE COLD CUTS,
THE PREPARED FOODS,
THE CHEESES, THE OLIVES,
THE WHOLE GIDDYAP.
WE WANT TO SHOW
THE REAL ITALIAN.
OH, YOU GUYS ARE CLASSIC.
(woman) BRASATO.
THANK YOU.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE THE ITALIAN
VERSION OF ROAST BEEF.
ALL RIGHT, SO WHAT
ARE WE GONNA MAKE FIRST?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE BRASATO
FOR OUR SANDWICH SPECIAL.
OKAY.
NOW THE BRASATO IS BEEF
THAT IS BRAISED
WITH WHITE WINE.
START WITH THE CARROTS,
CELERY,
ONIONS, BAY LEAVES,
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
A LITTLE WHITE WINE.
WHITE WINE.
GARLIC. LIGHTLY--
THAT'S NOT LIGHTLY. THAT'S LIKE,
"WHERE'S THE MONEY YOU OWE ME?"
A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
COARSE GROUND PEPPER.
OF COURSE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA
BAKE THIS AT 350
FOR ABOUT FOUR HOURS.
DIG IT.
WHAT KIND OF BREAD
ARE WE GONNA PUT IT ON?
ON OUR 12-INCH ROLLS.
12-INCH ROLLS THAT
YOU BAKE IN-HOUSE?
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL RIGHT.
SO WE'VE HAD A CHANCE
TO COOL DOWN.
TAKE US
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
BRING IT OVER
TO THE SLICER.
IT'S LIKE A TICKER TAPE PARADE
IN FLAVOR TOWN.
THIS IS THE SALSA ROSA.
BEEF.
A LITTLE BIT OF LETTUCE.
A FEW TOMATOES.
CUT IT RIGHT DOWN
THE MIDDLE.
I'LL PLATE IT.
I WISH THAT MY FATHER-IN-LAW
BOB WAS HERE.
WE LOST BOB TO CANCER.
THIS WAS THE KIND OF STUFF--
GO AROUND, FIND KILLER DELIS
IN THE GREATER PROVIDENCE AREA.
NOW, BOB, WHAT DO
YOU THINK, BROTHER?
MMM.
TENDER MEAT,
HOMEMADE BREAD,
ALL THE RIGHT SPICE,
ALL THE RIGHT FLAVOR.
MMM. AWESOME.
JACKPOT. NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(Massimo) BRASATO
WITH THE WORKS.
MY FAVORITE PART
IS THE SALSA ROSA--
A LITTLE SPICY,
BUT SWEET AT THE SAME TIME.
FLAVORS ARE AMAZING.
AND WHILE THE COUNTER
IS CRANKING DURING THE WEEK,
THESE DUDES REALLY KNOW HOW TO
THROW DOWN COME SATURDAY NIGHT.
ORDER UP.
THAT'S WHEN THIS JOINT
GOES SIT-DOWN.
SO WHY NOT A FULL-BLOWN
RESTAURANT EVERY DAY, ALL DAY?
EH, IT'S TOO MUCH WORK.
WE DON'T WANT TO GET KILLED.
SO WHEN WE COME BACK...
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
MEAT TORTELLINI.
A SATURDAY NIGHT SPECIAL...
DEPTH OF FLAVOR GALORE.
USING ALL THE TOOLS
OF THE TRADE.
NO WAY.
WELCOME BACK. TRIPLE "D"
HANGING IN EAST PROVIDENCE
AT THE ITALIAN CORNER
WITH MY BUDDY MASSIMO.
NOW WE ARE IN A SPECIAL ROOM.
WHAT ROOM IS THIS?
THIS IS THE PASTA ROOM.
YOU KNOW HOW COOL YOU ARE
WHEN YOU HAVE A PLACE
CALLED THE PASTA ROOM?
ALL IMPORTED FROM ITALY?
THE MACHINES, YES,
ALL FROM MILANO.
YOU, TOO.
I--FROM MILANO.
AND WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
MEAT TORTELLINI.
YEAH.
FLOUR, GENERAL PURPOSE.
SEMOLINA.
WE'RE GONNA START
THESE TWO FIRST.
OKAY, EGGS
AND A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
SO NOW WE MIXY MIX.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE FILLING FOR THE TORTELLINI.
YES, THE MEAT FILLING.
OKAY.
THE BASIS OF IT
IS THE BEEF.
THE BEEF
AND THEN THE PORK.
SO WE GRIND BRASATO.
GRIND BRASATO,
WE GRIND THE MORTADELLA. UH,
WE WILL GRIND SOME PROSCIUTTO
AND ALSO SOME SALAMI.
WE PUT IN
THE PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
NICE.
BREAD CRUMBS,
WHICH HELP ABSORB
THE MOISTURE.
AND SALT.
PASTA IS NOT SALTED,
SO IT WILL ABSORB
SOME OF THE SALT
FROM THE FILLING ITSELF.
GOT IT.
SO WE MIX IT BY HAND, RUN IT
THROUGH THE GRINDER AGAIN
TO REALLY COMBINE EVERYTHING,
THEN THE FILLING'S READY TO GO
INTO THE TORTELLINI MACHINE.
CORRECT.
IT'S LIKE FOOD CHRISTMAS.
PASTA IS READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND IT'S JUST THICK ENOUGH
AND JUST
AT THE RIGHT SPEED
THAT IT JUST
ROLLS ITSELF UP.
ALL RIGHT.
SO THE PASTA'S ON,
SO WE FEED THE HOPPER.
AND I'LL START OFF
FEEDING THE PASTA
RIGHT THROUGH.
JUST GONNA HIT THE LEVER,
AND TORTELLINIS
POP OUT.
NO WAY.
IT'S ABOUT FOUR
TO A SECOND.
THAT IS SO COOL.
AND THAT IS YOUR
TORTELLINI BOLOGNESE.
I WANT ONE
FOR CHRISTMAS.
LOOK AT THAT.
NOW WE GO MAKE
THE RAGU BOLOGNESE.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, ONIONS.
SO A LITTLE MIREPOIX.
ABSOLUTELY.
CELERY, CARROTS,
PORK JOWL--
GUANCIALE.
INSTEAD OF PANCETTA.
RIGHT THERE, BABY.
NOW WE GO IN
WITH THE GROUND BEEF.
GROUND BEEF.
WE'RE GONNA ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF WHITE WINE TO THIS.
FANTASTIC.
WE CAN START ADDING
OUR, UH, PORK PRODUCTS.
SALAMI, MORTADELLA,
AND THEN THE PROSCIUTTO.
LAST STEP,
WE HAVE TOMATO PASTE.
IMPORTED?
NO, DOMESTIC.
WHOO-HOO, WOW,
ONE THING.
WE'LL ADD SOME WATER
JUST TO BREAK THIS DOWN.
WE'LL COOK THIS DOWN
FOR HOW LONG?
UH, ABOUT TWO HOURS.
REALLY? GONNA LET IT SIMMER
FOR TWO HOURS.
YES.
THEN WE DROP THE TORTELLINI.
HOW LONG IS THAT GONNA COOK?
12 MINUTES.
OKAY, THE PASTA IS READY,
SAUCE IS READY.
PUT SOME OF THE SAUCE
IN OUR SAUTé PAN.
ONCE ALL THE PASTA
IS NICE AND COATED...
A LITTLE AMALGAMATION.
I WILL SHUT THIS OFF
AND ADD THE CHEESE.
AND THAT'S JUST GONNA MELT THERE
AND JUST TIGHTEN IT UP,
AMALGAMATE,
JUST BRING ALL THAT MIXTURE,
THAT SAUCE
STICKS TO THAT TORTELLINI.
OH, I'M GONNA SO HAVE
TO PUSH THE CAR
ALL THE WAY BACK TO CALIFORNIA
JUST TO WORK THIS OFF.
FEEL THE FOOD COMA
ALERT COMING ON.
THIS IS ONLY AVAILABLE
ON SATURDAY NIGHTS.
OR YOU COULD COME IN
AND BUY IT...
CORRECT.
AND COOK IT AT HOME.
WAIT.
A LITTLE BIT OF CHEESE.
GREAT CHEW TO THE PASTA.
IT'S TENDER.
IT'S FLAVORFUL.
IT'S NOT TOO SALTY.
IT'S NOT TOO ANYTHING.
THE BOLOGNESE
IS ALMOST CREAMY.
DEPTH OF FLAVOR GALORE.
THE PASTA IS NOT A CASTLE,
SO THEREFORE
IT SHOULD NOT BE FLOATING
IN A MOAT OF SAUCE THERE.
NOPE.
THIS IS OUTSTANDING.
REAL ESTATE VALUES IN
EAST PROVIDENCE JUST WENT UP.
AWESOME.
THANK YOU.
(woman) TORTELLINI RAGU.
THE SAUCE, HANDS DOWN
THE BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
I HAVE TOLD YOU GUYS
MANY TIMES
ABOUT LORI'S FAMILY LIVING HERE
IN PROVIDENCE, RHODE ISLAND.
SO, AUNT MARLENE,
UNCLE ALAN, JEN,
YOU GUYS GOTTA TELL ME,
OUT OF ALL THE ITALIAN FOOD,
HOW DID THESE GUYS
STACK UP?
AMAZING.
VERY GOOD.
JUST LIKE MAMA
USED TO MAKE.
PLACE IS OFF THE HOOK.
THE ATMOSPHERE IS CASUAL,
BUT YET THE FOOD IS LIKE YOU'RE
IN SOMEONE'S ITALIAN KITCHEN.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
CRAZY.
I'M COMING BACK,
OKAY, AND YOU ARE GONNA MAKE ME
SOME PASTA ON A TUESDAY.
ABSOLUTELY.
I CAN GET SOME
FROZEN TO GO?
YEAH.
GOOD. LOAD UP THE CAR.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
WE'VE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪