HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
I'M JUST GONNA HOLD ON,
'CAUSE THIS LOOKS LIKE
IT'S GONNA BE A ROUGH RIDE.
DON'T ASK ME WHY.
IT'S JUST FOOD THAT WORKS.
NOT SOMETHING
YOU SEE EVERY DAY IN A BAR.
IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE...
SOUTH OF BEALE--
YOU GET IT?
THE BAR/FUNKY FOOD JOINT
THAT'S HOME OF THE FREE...
THAT IS ROCKIN' IT
OLD SCHOOL.
THE UNUSUAL...
LOVE ME SOME
DUCK FRIED RICE.
AND THE DOWNRIGHT TASTY.
WOW.
WHO WOULD HAVE THUNK?
IN HALEIWA, OAHU...
(rooster crows)
IS THAT THE NEXT MEAL
THAT'S MAKING NOISE?
A RESTAURANT ON WHEELS...
(whistles)
RIDIN'
THE STEAK-AND-SHRIMP WAVE
ALL THE WAY TO FLAVOR-TOWN.
AND IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND...
THAT'S RIGHT, IT'S ROUND TWO
OF CHAPS PIT BEEF.
I'M BACK...
EXPLAIN IT AGAIN.
IT'S NOT ROCKET SCIENCE.
FOR MORE PIT BEEF.
(Guy) DO YOU THINK THAT ONE
NAPKIN IS GONNA SUFFICE?
ENOUGH SAID.
I FEEL LIKE A LITTLE KID GETTING
READY TO BLOW OUT THE CANDLES
ON THE BIRTHDAY CAKE.
GET THAT HAND
OUT OF THERE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW, EVERY MAJOR CITY
IN THE UNITED STATES
HAS, LIKE, THAT ICONIC STREET.
IN NEW YORK,
WELL, IT'S BROADWAY.
UH, NEW ORLEANS,
IT WOULD BE BOURBON STREET.
HERE IN MEMPHIS, IT'S BEALE
STREET, AND IT'S RIGHT UP THERE.
SO WHEN YOU'RE CRUISIN' ON BEALE
STREET AND HANG A RIGHT ON MAIN,
YOU'D BE GOING--WELL,
YOU'D BE GOING SOUTH OF BEALE.
OHH, THAT'D BE A GREAT NAME
FOR A RESTAURANT.
SOUTH OF BEALE--YOU GET IT?
(woman) GUY!
HEY THERE.
(man) STEAK SALAD.
WELL, IT'S NOT YOUR STANDARD
GREASY BAR FOOD.
(man) HERE'S OUR LEEK AND ASIAGO
MAC N CHEESE.
(man) IT'S DEFINITELY NOT A BAR.
IT'S A RESTAURANT
THAT HAPPENS
TO HAVE GOOD DRINKS.
THE IDEAL GASTROPUB.
DRAWN UP BY FOOD INDUSTRY VETS
BRITTANY AND ED CABIGAO.
WE'VE BEEN SERVERS,
MANAGERS...
LADIES.
BARTENDERS.
IT DEFINITELY SEEMED
LIKE A NATURAL PROGRESSION.
AND CHEF BRYAN McDANIEL'S
ECLECTIC MENU
IS MAKING THIS PLACE
A MID-SOUTH HOT SPOT.
SO MANY NEAT THINGS
THAT YOU CAN COME IN AND HAVE
THAT YOU WOULDN'T EXPECT.
WE'RE TALKIN'
PULLED PORK EGG ROLLS
TOPPED WITH
DR PEPPER CURRY SAUCE
BUTTERSCOTCH MOUSSE AND
THIS TAKE ON A CHINESE CLASSIC.
DUCK FRIED RICE.
THIS IS ONE OF THE DISHES THAT
PEOPLE ACTUALLY COME HERE FOR.
WE'RE GONNA DO
A DUCK FRIED RICE.
I LIKE IT.
NOT SOMETHING YOU SEE EVERY DAY
IN A BAR. OKAY, FIRE IT UP.
THIS IS JUST REGULAR,
RUN-OF-THE-MILL DUCK.
HE PROBABLY DOESN'T APPRECIATE
BEING CALLED THAT. HE'S...
BUT, I MEAN,
HE'S A TELEVISION STAR NOW.
WELL, GOOD, GOOD.
SO WE'LL BREAK HIM DOWN.
SO WE'RE GONNA USE
THE THIGH AND THE LEG.
AND THAT'S ALL GOING
FOR FRIED RICE?
YES, IT IS.
LOVE ME SOME
DUCK FRIED RICE.
OKAY. POP IT IN THE PAN,
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE DUCK FAT,
COVER IT UP, HIT IT IN THE OVEN.
WHAT TEMP?
ABOUT 350
FOR ABOUT 5 TO 6 HOURS.
COMES OUT FORK-TENDER,
SHRED IT.
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF OUR DUCK
FAT THAT WE'VE RENDERED OFF.
THE FOOD LUBE.
THE FOOD LUBE,
THERE YOU GO.
SOME MINCED GARLIC,
SOME DICED GINGER.
OKAY.
AND WE'RE ALSO GONNA ADD
A PORTION OF OUR RENDERED DUCK
THAT WE'VE USED
AND SOME GREEN ONIONS.
OKAY.
WHILE ALL THAT'S WORKING, WE'RE
GONNA MAKE OUR FIVE-SPICE.
SO YOU'RE MAKING YOUR OWN
CHINESE FIVE-SPICE?
YES.
SOME GROUND CINNAMON
AND THEN SOME STAR ANISE
AND SOME CARDAMOM.
ALL RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER
AND SOME FENNEL.
WOW.
SO THEN ONCE OUR DUCK
GETS HEATED UP,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR SPICE TO IT,
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE
SOME STEAMED JASMINE RICE,
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE SOY SAUCE.
AND WHILE THAT'S WORKING,
WE'RE GONNA DO SOME--
A LITTLE BIT
OF SRIRACHA HOT SAUCE
JUST FOR A LITTLE BIT
OF A LOVELY KICK.
AND NOW WHILE THAT'S HEATING UP,
WE'RE GONNA TAKE ANOTHER PAN
WITH A LITTLE MORE FOOD LUBE,
AS WE CALL IT.
AND WE WILL PUT A DELICIOUS
SUNNY-SIDE EGG.
OH, DON'T TELL ME THAT
THAT'S THE SECRET INGREDIENT.
SOMEBODY'S GETTIN' IT.
HIT THE EGG WITH SOME
OF OUR FIVE-SPICE.
OKAY.
YEP, WE'RE GOOD NOW. JUST
WAITING ON OUR EGG TO FINISH.
♪♪♪
(gags)
THAT'S A BIG'N.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THE CONFIT OF THE DUCK,
SAVE SOME OF THE DUCK FAT
TO LUBE THE PAN,
COLD RICE,
MAKE YOUR OWN FIVE-SPICE.
THAT'S NICE.
MMM. MMM.
I DON'T MAKE
MY OWN FIVE-SPICE,
BUT AFTER TASTING THAT,
I THINK I WOULD.
YOU'VE PICKED UP THE NICE NOTES
OF IT. IT'S NUTTY. OHH.
MMM. AND THE DUCK...
IS SUPER TENDER.
I SAVED SOME OF THE EGG FOR YOU.
THAT'S
THE PIèCE DE RéSISTANCE.
OH, IT IS. THAT IS A PIECE
THAT I TRY TO RESIST.
A LITTLE BIT
OF SCALLION IN THERE,
HINT OF THE GINGER
AND THE GARLIC, SOME SOY,
AND THE DUCK... MMM.
THIS IS GREAT.
HOW MUCH IS THIS?
$5.
NO, IT'S NOT.
IS IT THAT BIG
OF A PORTION?
THAT'S OUR PORTION
RIGHT THERE.
DUDE, THAT'S EXCELLENT.
DUCK FRIED RICE.
5 BUCKS
FOR THAT FRIED RICE.
5 BUCKS.
RIDICULOUS.
OH, YOU HAVE NO IDEA.
BECAUSE HERE AT SOUTH OF BEALE,
CRAZY LOW PRICES
ARE ALL PART OF THE DEAL.
(man) MAPLE BACON BRAISED
BRUSSELS SPROUTS.
WE COME HERE SO OFTEN, AND
IT'S BECAUSE WE CAN COME HERE
IN LIEU OF EATING AT HOME
AND NOT BREAK OUR BANK.
SOME POPCORN.
AND IT DOESN'T GET ANY CHEAPER
THAN THIS STARTER SNACK.
ON EVERY TABLE, THERE'S ALWAYS
A WONDERFUL BOWL OF POPCORN.
SOMETHING
A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
IT'S JUST THE PERFECT SNACK.
ALL RIGHT,
THE PRESTO POPPER.
I HAVEN'T HAD ONE OF THESE
SINCE I WAS A KID.
I BELIEVE THEY CALL THAT
KICKING IT OLD SCHOOL.
THAT IS ROCKIN' IT
OLD SCHOOL.
OKAY,
SO WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
IT'S OUR HOUSE POPCORN.
SO FIRE THIS THING UP.
JUST LIKE MOM USED TO DO, WE'RE
GONNA DUMP IN SOME KERNELS,
LET THEM START
WORKING THEIR MAGIC.
OKAY.
AND WHILE WE'RE WAITING
FOR THE POPCORN TO POP,
WE'LL START MAKING
OUR HOUSE SPICE.
WE TAKE BROWN SUGAR
THAT WE HAVE DEHYDRATED
AND GROUND UP
INTO A POWDER FORM.
SO YOU GET A BUNCH
OF THE MOISTURE OUT
SO IT'S NOT HEAVY
AND CLUMPY.
THEN WE'LL ADD A MIXTURE
OF OUR HOUSE BLACKENING SPICE
TO IT, KOSHER SALT,
PAPRIKA,
SOME CAYENNE PEPPER,
CUMIN,
SOME BLACK PEPPER,
DRY MUSTARD...
MY KIND OF POPCORN.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF GRANULATED GARLIC...
OKAY.
JUST 'CAUSE GARLIC
MAKES EVERYTHING BETTER.
WE'LL GIVE THIS A LITTLE STIR,
BLEND IT ALL TOGETHER.
AND IT GETS MIXED INTO
THE BROWN SUGAR?
YES.
AND IT'S ALREADY
STARTING TO POP.
ARE WE GONNA DO THE
BUTTER-MELTING THING UP TOP?
KICK A LITTLE BUTTER
ON TOP.
THIS IS NUTS.
ACTUALLY, IT'S POPCORN.
NOW ONCE OUR POPCORN
HAS POPPED,
WE'LL TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF OUR
BUTTER THAT WE'VE MELTED UP TOP.
AND YOU GIVE THIS TO PEOPLE
FOR FREE WHEN THEY COME IN?
YES, INDEED.
I DON'T THINK WE'VE EVER COOKED
ANYTHING ON TRIPLE "D"
THAT WE GIVE AWAY
FOR FREE.
SO NOW WE'LL TAKE
SOME OF OUR HOUSE SPICE.
YOU'RE JUST PUNCHING THE KETTLE
CORN GUY IN THE HEAD WITH THIS.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
VOILà.
HUH.
OHH. IT'S GREAT.
SEE, IT'S NOT KETTLE CORN.
IT'S NOT THAT SUPERSWEET
KETTLE CORN STUFF.
IT'S NOT STICKY. WHEN YOU
PUT IT TOWARDS YOUR MOUTH,
YOU'RE GETTIN'
ALL THOSE SPICES.
MMM.
SALTY, CRUNCHY...
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER,
AND FREE.
LET ME BACK IT UP.
IT'S FREE...
AND IT HAS OTHER STUFF.
(laughs)
AWESOME JOB.
THE POPCORN IS VERY ADDICTIVE.
NOWHERE ELSE IN MEMPHIS
HAS ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
IT'S DEFINITELY UNIQUE
TO SOUTH OF BEALE.
I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING--
DUCK FRIED RICE--
OUT OF BOUNDS.
FREE POPCORN--AS MUCH
AS I CAN SHOVEL IN MY MOUTH.
YOU GOTTA LOVE IT.
SO WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA DO
A JACK AND COKE BREAD PUDDING.
WE'RE SOUTH OF BEALE--S.O.B.--
HANGING OUT WITH CHEF BRYAN.
IS THAT YOUR SPOON?
OH.
I'M IN, LIKE, SOME KIND
OF A POPCORN COMA.
I'M HANGING OUT
WITH CHEF BRYAN
AT SOUTH OF BEALE
IN MEMPHIS.
DUDE, WHAT HAVE YOU
DONE TO ME?
I'VE NEVER EATEN THAT MUCH
POPCORN IN MY LIFE.
SERIOUSLY,
SOMEONE TAKE IT AWAY.
HOPEFULLY WE'RE ON TO SOMETHING
NICE AND LIGHT NOW.
WE'RE GONNA DO
A JACK AND COKE BREAD PUDDING.
DURING COMMERCIAL,
HE WHISPERED AND SAID,
"YOU WANT
A JACK AND COKE?"
I'M LIKE, RIGHT ON.
YOU DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT BREAD PUDDING.
FIRE IT UP.
WHAT DO WE GOT?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR CUSTARD BASE
FOR OUR BREAD PUDDING.
YES, WE ARE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR EGG YOLKS
AND THEN SOME SUGAR,
HEAVY CREAM,
AND THEN WE MAKE
A COCA-COLA REDUCTION.
SO YOU TAKE THE SYRUP OF COLA,
REDUCE IT DOWN...
YES.
SO IT TURNS
INTO THIS TRUE SYRUP--
NOW IT'S ALMOST
LIKE MOLASSES--
AND MIX THAT ALL TOGETHER
TO MAKE THE CUSTARD
THAT'S GONNA
GO OVER THE TOP OF THIS?
YES.
AND WHAT BREADS
DO WE HAVE IN HERE?
UH, WE'VE GOT
A HULA BREAD,
WHICH IS A SWEETER
HAWAIIAN BREAD.
SWEET HAWAIIAN BREAD.
WE'VE GOT JUST A REGULAR--
A HOAGIE ROLL.
WE DUMP OUR BREAD IN, ADD
OUR CUSTARD THAT WE JUST MADE.
WOW.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA
SMASH OUR BREAD DOWN
SO IT SOAKS UP
ALL OF THE CUSTARD.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA
COVER IN FOIL...
RIGHT.
COOK IT OFF IN THE OVEN
AT ABOUT 350
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR,
HOUR AND A HALF.
PULL IT OUT.
WHEN'S THE JACK DANIEL'S GETTING
INVITED TO THIS PARTY?
THAT'S THE NEXT STEP.
SO WE'VE GOT AN ICE CREAM MAKER
WITH FROZEN INSIDES.
AND, UH, THIS IS GONNA BE
NICE, QUICK, AND FAST.
LET'S SEE IT.
SO FOR OUR ICE CREAM BASE,
IT'S GONNA BE MILK,
HEAVY CREAM,
SOME SUGAR,
AND OUR OLD BUDDY
JACK HERE.
LET HIM KIND OF HANG OUT
FOR A LITTLE BIT.
LOOKIN' GOOD.
THERE YOU GO. NICE JOB.
GIVE IT A LITTLE STIR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR BASE
TO THE ICE CREAM MIXER.
AND WE CAN
TURN IT ON NOW.
AND THAT'S ALL
SHE WROTE, HUH?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
HOW LONG
IS THIS GONNA RUN?
SHE'LL RUN
FOR ABOUT 20, 30 MINUTES.
THIS WILL MAKE US
ABOUT 2 QUARTS.
NICE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR ICE CREAM IN THE FREEZER
FOR ABOUT TWO TO THREE HOURS
TO FINISH HARDENING.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR COOKED BREAD PUDDING,
GET A LITTLE PIECE
READY TO GO.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR ICE CREAM--
THROW YOU A BIG SCOOP ON TOP,
HOW ABOUT THAT?
THEN WE'RE GONNA FINISH IT
WITH OUR COLA SYRUP THAT WE DID.
AND THAT'S READY TO GO.
NICE.
WOW.
WHO WOULD HAVE THUNK?
YOU GOT NOTHING WRONG
WITH THIS, BUDDY.
YOU GOT GREAT--SEE...
(groans)
BRAIN FREEZE.
I DON'T LIKE WHEN BREAD PUDDING
GETS ALL MUSHY, MUSHY, MUSHY.
RIGHT.
IT'S GOT A NICE CRUNCH ON THE
BOTTOM, NICE CRUNCH ON THE TOP.
MMM. SO YOU GOT
GREAT FLAVOR IN IT.
YOU DEFINITELY PICK UP
THE JACK DANIEL'S IN THE...
IN THE ICE CREAM.
AND THEN THE COLA SYRUP
OVER THE TOP OF THAT
JUST BRINGS IT
RIGHT BACK HOME.
THIS RIGHT HERE, THIS IS WHY
I CAN'T MOVE TO MEMPHIS.
MMM. OH, THAT'S GREAT.
THAT'S REALLY TASTY, MAN.
GOT A JACK AND COKE
BREAD PUDDING IN THE WINDOW.
(woman)
IT'S A LITTLE BIT CRUNCHY,
AND IT ALSO HAS THE SWEET FLAVOR
OF THE ICE CREAM.
IT'S SWEET,
BUT IT'S A LITTLE TANGY ALMOST
WITH THE JACK AND COKE.
I MEAN, FOR THE BAR AND
EVERYTHING AND THE OTHER FOOD,
YOU GUYS GIVE 'EM A DEAL,
KEEP 'EM COMING BACK.
GIVING 'EM A DEAL,
SOUTH OF BEALE.
YEAH!
(laughter)
UP NEXT...
WHAT'S NOT TO LIKE ABOUT THIS?
WE'RE HANGIN' TEN
ON OAHU'S NORTH SHORE,
ROCKIN' THE BUS
WITH A LITTLE SURF...
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
GETTING SHRIMP ON THE ISLAND.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
AND TURF.
I LOVE IT. YOU SHOULD BE,
LIKE, THE MAYOR OR SOMETHING.
♪♪♪
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IN CASE YOU HAVEN'T NOTICED,
THE FOOD TRUCK INVASION
HAS HAPPENED.
I MEAN, WE'RE SEEING 'EM
EVERYWHERE--
TEXAS, LOS ANGELES, VANCOUVER,
YOU NAME IT,
AND NOW, HERE ON THE ISLAND
OF OAHU IN THE NORTH SHORE.
THIS IS THE BIG WAVE SHRIMP
TRUCK.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG
EATIN' AT BIG WAVE SHRIMP.
(laughs)
ABSOLUTELY PERFECT.
EVERYONE'S FAVORITE PLACE
ON OAHU TO EAT.
HOW'S THE FOOD?
AMAZING, ALWAYS.
HOW LONG AGO
DID THIS HAPPEN?
ALMOST SIX YEARS ALREADY.
SIX YEARS AGO?
THAT'S WHEN MIKE STACY
GAVE HIS WIFE KATE
SOMETHING SHE'S ALWAYS WANTED,
HER OWN RESTAURANT.
THEN YOU BUILD HER
A TRUCK?
YEAH. IT USED TO BE
A HANDI-VAN BUS.
AND YOU TOOK IT AND CONVERTED IT
INTO A RESTAURANT ON WHEELS?
YES.
SPICY SHRIMP.
AND STARTED CRANKING OUT THEIR
TAKE ON NORTH SHORE STAPLES.
SO LOCAL STYLE
IS HAWAIIAN STYLE,
BUT YOU PUT
YOUR THAI FLAIR TO IT?
CORRECT.
SO WHAT KIND OF FOOD
DO YOU MAKE HERE?
THE MAIN THING
IS THE SHRIMPS.
THE SHRIMPS?
BUT YOU MAKE OTHER THINGS.
YES.
FROM SHOYU CHICKEN
AND LOCALLY GROWN SWEET CORN
TO KATE'S
KOREAN-STYLE SHORT RIBS...
THESE ARE JUST,
LIKE, PERFECT.
WITH A RECIPE I GUARANTEE
YOU WON'T FORGET.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA
MAKE FIRST?
BARBECUE SHORT RIBS
FOR YOU.
FOR ME?
YES.
I'M JUST GONNA HOLD ON,
'CAUSE THIS LOOKS LIKE
IT'S GONNA BE A ROUGH RIDE.
IT'S FUN.
(laughs)
OKAY, I'M SORRY.
I START--
CUT THE SHORT RIB.
THEN YOU SEASON?
THIS IS THE CHICKEN BROTH
SEASONING.
CHICKEN BASE AND A LITTLE BIT
OF GARLIC SALT.
CORRECT.
ARE YOU OPEN EVERY DAY?
SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
(rooster crows)
IS THAT THE NEXT MEAL
THAT'S MAKING NOISE?
MAYBE.
(laughs)
THIS SITS HERE WITH THE DRY RUB
ON IT FOR HOW LONG?
IT'S ABOUT
ONE OR TWO HOURS.
BUT IT ABSORBS
SOME OF THE FLAVOR...
RIGHT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
COOK IT IN THE PAN.
MM-HMM.
A LITTLE OIL.
THIS IS A THIN SLICE, WHICH IS
MORE THE ASIAN OR KOREAN STYLE.
JUST BECAUSE OF THE BONE
AND THE CONNECTIVE TISSUE,
IT'S ALMOST SWEET,
REAL GREAT BEEF FLAVOR.
AND THAT'S JUST IT,
NICE AND SIMPLE, HUH?
PRETTY EASY.
CHICKEN BASE
AND GARLIC SALT.
♪ CHICKEN BASE AND GARLIC SALT,
CHICKEN BASE AND GARLIC SALT ♪
♪ CHICKEN BASE
AND GARLIC SALT FOR ME ♪
NOW SING IT. IT'S...
♪ CHICKEN BASE AND GARLIC SALT ♪
♪ CHICKEN BASE
AND GARLIC SALT FOR ME ♪
(Kate laughs)
NEXT SEASONING,
HONDASHI.
HONDASHI
IS AN ASIAN SEASON SALT.
AND THEN ON
THE RICE, FURIKAKE.
FURIKAKE IS A TRADITIONAL
HAWAIIAN, ASIAN--
WE PUT IT ON SUSHI
AT TEX WASABI A LOT.
IT'S READY NOW.
THE SHORT RIBS?
YES, SIR.
(laughs)
I LOVE IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
NICE AND CRISPY.
ANYTHING I CAN EAT WITH
MY HANDS, OF COURSE, I WANT TO.
THE SHORT RIB JUST BY ITSELF,
IT'S GOT GREAT FLAVOR.
YOU GET A LITTLE BIT OF THE RICE
WITH THE FURIKAKE
WITH A BITE
OF THE SHORT RIB.
WHAT'S NOT TO LIKE
ABOUT THIS?
BARBECUED SHORT RIBS.
THEY'RE REALLY JUICY,
AND THEY'RE NOT OVERCOOKED.
THE RIBS ARE REALLY GOOD.
THERE'S A LOT
OF DIFFERENT FLAVOR TO IT.
AND EVERYTHING THAT THEY MAKE
IS HANDMADE, REAL DEAL?
EVERYTHING.
THIS IS A LOCALS' TOWN?
DEFINITELY.
HERE ON THE NORTH SHORE,
THE LOCALS KNOW THEIR WAVES,
AND THEY KNOW THEIR SHRIMP.
I'M A JUNKIE,
A SHRIMP JUNKIE.
SO ALL KINDS OF SHRIMP HERE
ON THE SHRIMP TRUCK?
LEMON PEPPER SHRIMP.
I ALREADY KNOW WHAT
YOU WANT--COCONUT SHRIMP.
(laughs)
I AM HAVING THE SPICY SHRIMP,
AND IT IS EXCELLENT.
(Mike) CRUNCHY SHRIMP.
I'M HAVING
THE CRUNCHY SHRIMP.
I MEAN, I LIKE IT.
IT'S TASTY.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THE BATTER
FOR THIS.
FOR THE CRUNCHY SHRIMP?
YES, SIR.
TEMPURA.
TEMPURA BATTER.
SUGAR.
SUGAR?
MAKE IT SWEETER.
NO CHICKEN BASE
OR GARLIC SALT?
NO MORE.
THAT'S ALL.
SO THAT'S A 21/25 SHRIMP,
BUTTERFLIED ALL THE WAY OPEN,
NO SHELL.
OKAY, SO WE DIP 'EM
IN THE BATTER...
YES.
INTO THE PANKO.
PANKO.
LET THAT KIND OF
STICK ON THERE.
VEGETABLE OIL.
NOW WE ARE READY
TO PUT IT IN THE PAN.
EVERY TIME SOMEBODY ORDERS
SOMETHING, MAKE IT TO SCRATCH?
YES, EVERY TIME.
(whistles)
AND WE COOK FAST.
AFTER WE FINISH,
WE PUT ON THE PLATE.
TEN PIECES?
MMM.
SWEET-AND-SOUR
OR SWEET CHILI?
SWEET CHILI.
MMM.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT GETTING
SHRIMP ON THE ISLAND.
WHEN THEY'RE NOT FROZEN,
SO TENDER.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
CRAZY.
THEY'RE GREAT.
(Mike) CRUNCHY SHRIMP.
IT'S JUST INSANE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
AS SOON AS IT HITS YOUR MOUTH,
IT JUST, LIKE--MMM--MELTS.
MAKE ALL THESE
PEOPLE HAPPY--
YOU SHOULD BE, LIKE,
THE MAYOR OR SOMETHING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE THIS PLACE.
COMING UP...
WHEN I ROLL BACK INTO BALTIMORE,
THERE'S ONE JOINT
I GOTTA CHECK OUT.
WE'RE HEADED BACK TO ONE OF
TRIPLE "D's" ALL-TIME FAVES...
YOU GUYS ARE THE ORIGINATOR,
NOT THE IMITATOR.
TO SEE HOW THINGS
ARE STACKING UP.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
♪♪♪
YOU KNOW, IF THERE IS ONE
QUESTION YOU GUYS ALL ASK ME,
IT'S, "GUY, DO YOU HAVE
A FAVORITE TRIPLE 'D' JOINT?"
WELL, THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY,
BUT I'LL TELL YOU THIS,
WHEN I ROLL BACK INTO BALTIMORE,
THERE'S ONE JOINT
I GOTTA CHECK OUT.
THAT'S RIGHT, IT'S ROUND TWO
OF CHAPS PIT BEEF.
YOU COME TO BALTIMORE,
THIS IS WHAT YOU BETTER SEE.
AND IF YOU DON'T,
IT'S NOT PIT BEEF.
THE CHARCOAL PIT BEEF--YOU'RE
NOT GONNA GET IT NOWHERE ELSE.
ONE MEDIUM-RARE BEEF
ON A ROLL.
IT IS SO TENDER.
JUST FALLS RIGHT APART.
DONE THE WAY YOU WANT...
MEDIUM-WELL.
THEN SLICED THIN...
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
AND PILED HIGH.
THAT'S THE BEST BEEF
I'VE EVER HAD.
WHEN ANYBODY SAYS CHAPS, THEY
KNOW WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
IT STARTED OVER 20 YEARS AGO
WHEN BOB AND DONNA CREAGER
GOT MARRIED.
AS A WEDDING GIFT, MY FATHER
GAVE ME THIS LITTLE SHACK.
I HAVEN'T FOUND A JOINT
LIKE IT IN THE COUNTRY.
DO PEOPLE CALL AND SAY,
"HOW DO I GET THERE?"
ALL DAY.
THEY COME FROM CONNECTICUT,
THEY COME FROM FLORIDA,
THEY COME FROM OHIO.
AND HE CAME FROM DELAWARE
TO GET SOME PIT BEEF.
EVEN THOUGH YOU'VE BECOME SUPER
POPULAR, EVERYBODY LOVES YOU,
PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD,
YOU STILL MAKE IT THE SAME WAY.
WE'RE NOT CHANGING IT.
DIDN'T CHANGE A THING?
NO, SIR.
I GIVE IT WAY PAST A TEN.
IT'S NOT ROCKET SCIENCE.
REALLY GOOD PREMIUM MEAT, DRY
RUB, A LITTLE BIT OF SEASONING,
COOKING IT OVER THE LUMP
CHARCOAL, NOT THE BRIQUETTES.
SLICE IT THIN,
SERVE IT ON GOOD PRODUCT.
YOU GOT IT.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
MMM, THIS IS GREAT, MAN.
HOW'S BUSINESS?
GREAT.
BEEN OFF THE HOOK.
YOU GOT A LOT OF PEOPLE.
ONE, TWO, THREE...
THERE'S LIKE TEN GUYS
WORKING RIGHT NOW.
USED TO BE FIVE
BEFORE YOU WERE HERE.
YOU MADE NEW MENU ITEMS, OR JUST
STICKING WITH WHAT YOU'VE HAD?
BEEF RACHEL.
BEEF RACHEL?
YEAH, KIND OF LIKE A REUBEN,
BUT WE USE BEEF INSTEAD.
INSTEAD OF SAUERKRAUT,
WE USE COLESLAW.
ONE BEEF RACHEL.
SO THE GUY'S
TRIPLE D DOES GOOD?
EXCELLENT.
SO YOU GUYS, IF YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENS,
IF YOU HAVEN'T SEEN
THE CHOPS TRIPLE "D,"
WHEN DUFF WAS HERE
WITH ME...
WHERE ARE YOU,
"DUFF-INATOR," MY BROTHER?
THAT--JUST LOOK
AT THE CASCADING JOY.
LOOK AT THE BITE
OUT OF THERE.
YOU GOT A GUY TRIPLE D
COMING?
(man) SURE DO.
THIS I GOTTA HAVE.
YOU SEE THAT RIGHT THERE?
SEE THAT GOODNESS?
THE CORNED BEEF, THE SAUSAGE,
AND THE ROAST BEEF...
GET THAT HAND
OUT OF THERE.
IT REALLY IS RIDICULOUS.
YOU NEED
SOME CONDIMENTS FOR IT?
I WANT SOME WHITE ONIONS,
A LITTLE BIT OF THE HORSERADISH
CUT WITH SOME MAYO...
THAT'S THE TIGER SAUCE.
AND SOME MUSTARD.
I FEEL LIKE A LITTLE KID GETTING
READY TO BLOW OUT THE CANDLES
ON THE BIRTHDAY CAKE.
LOOK AT THIS.
DONNA, HOW LONG'S IT BEEN
SINCE WE DID TRIPLE "D?"
THREE YEARS
AND, LIKE, THREE MONTHS.
HERE'S ROUND TWO.
RIDICULOUS.
DO YOU THINK THAT ONE NAPKIN
IS GONNA SUFFICE?
(Bob laughs)
MMM. AM I OKAY?
NOTHING THERE, RIGHT?
I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
IF YOU WANT TO FIND OUT
WHERE THE REAL DEAL, TRUE
BALTIMORE PIT BEEF COMES FROM,
YOU GOTTA COME
TO CHAPS PIT BEEF.
YOU GUYS ARE THE ORIGINATOR,
NOT THE IMITATOR.
IS THERE GONNA BE
A CHAPS 2?
WE'RE THINKING ABOUT IT.
WE WANT TO COME OUT
TO CALIFORNIA WITH YOU.
TWIST MY ARM.
DO NOT COME--LISTEN,
I'M TELLING YOU RIGHT NOW,
DO NOT LET THEM OPEN
IN A NEIGHBORHOOD NEAR YOU.
EVERYBODY WILL WEIGH
100 POUNDS MORE, I SWEAR.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS
FLAVOR-TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪ CHICKEN BASE
AND GARLIC SALT ♪
AND GARLIC SALT FOR ME ♪
♪ FOR ME ♪
WE'RE TAKING IT ON THE ROAD.
WE'RE ALREADY ON THE BUS.