HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
WE'RE SAMPLING
SOME OUT OF THE ORDINARY EATS...
AS FUNKY AS IT IS
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
WITH A SIDE OF LOVE.
ON THE EAST SIDE OF OAHU
RIGHT OFF THE DOCK, BABY.
A FUNKY JOINT HOSTED UP
AT THE END OF THE PIER.
NOW WHICH WAY DO YOU DO IT.
COUNTER "QWOK-WISE."
(Guy)
PUTTING ON A SHOW...
THAT'S PACKING IN THE PEOPLE.
THAT'S REAL BIG FLAVOR IN THAT.
(Guy)
IN CHICAGO, ILLINOIS...
EVERYBODY COME INTO THE STORE
IS LIKE, MY FRIEND.
(Guy)
AN ITALIAN SPOT
PUTTING A SICILIAN SPIN...
SCHIACCIATA,
IT MEANS FLATTENED IN ITALIAN.
(Guy)
ON THE GREAT GRILLED CHEESE.
IT'S LIKE
THIS GREAT BOLD AMAZINGNESS.
(Guy)
AND IN HERNANDO, MISSISSIPPI
THE CELLAR RESTAURANT...
THAT IS DECADENT.
(Guy)
PUTTING DESSERT BACK ON TOP.
IF I GAVE YOU A CHANCE
IN A SMALL JUNGLE
YOU'D PROBABLY GROW THE BANANAS.
THAT'S RIGHT, IN GUATEMALA.
YEP, ON HIS WAY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON "DINERS,
DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO HERE I AM
ON THE EAST COAST...
OF OAHU.
HENCE THE JEEP, ALL RIGHT.
SO I'M ABOUT 35 MINUTES
AWAY FROM WAIKIKI.
I'M SURROUNDED BY BOATS,
I'M ON A PIER, WHY?
WELL BECAUSE I HEAR
THERE'S A PLACE
THAT IS DOING SOME REAL-DEAL
HAWAIIAN FOOD.
I MEAN,
WE'RE TALKIN' OFF THE HOOK.
AND THAT WAS PUN INTENDED.
THIS IS HE'EIA KEA PIER
GENERAL STORE AND DELI.
FRESH FRIED VEGGIE SHOT.
IT'S A LITTLE HIDDEN GEM,
KIND OF
A HOLE-IN-THE-WALL PLACE
WHERE A WHOLE LOT OF
WAIKIKI TOURISTS
ARE GONNA FIND
GOOD LOCAL FOOD.
A NICE ATMOSPHERE
RIGHT ON THE WATER,
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
MISOYAKI BEEF.
HAWAIIAN-STYLE COMFORT FOOD
WITH A TWIST.
(Guy)
COOKED UP BY AN ISLAND NATIVE
LOCALS CALL GOOCH.
OH, SO WHERE'S THE GOOCH?
GOOCH.
(man)
GOOCH, HE'S CRAZY.
(Guy)
THAT'S CHEF MARK NOGUCHI.
WHOSE PASSION FOR COOKING
LED HIM TO
THE CULINARY INSTITUTE
OF AMERICA
AND WHOSE LOVE FOR OAHU
BROUGHT HIM BACK HOME.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GET BACK TO WORK.
(Guy)
NOW HE'S PUTTING HIS OWN SPIN
ON CLASSIC HAWAIIAN DISHES,
LIKE THIS PLATE LUNCH,
DELIVERED BOTH SALTY AND SWEET.
LUAH STEW FOR ANDREW.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING FIRST?
ALL RIGHT, SO FIRST TODAY
WE'RE GONNA MAKE LUAH STEW.
LUAH LIKE AMUKAMUKA...
NO, LUAH LEAF IS TARO LEAF.
TARA, LIKE TARO ROOT?
EXACTLY.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THIS BONELESS PORK SHOULDER,
TRIM OFF THE FAT,
AND DICE IT UP
FOR THE LUAH STEW.
SO THE PORK'S ALL CUBED UP,
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT WITH...
KOSHER SALT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA GO
TO THE RONDO AND BROWN IT OFF?
YEP.
OKAY, NOW WHAT'S NEXT?
NOW WE ADD OUR ONIONS,
ADD OUR SALT, AND...
PULL A LITTLE MOISTURE
OUT THERE, SWEAT THESE DOWN.
NOW THE ONIONS
HAVE DEFINITELY CARAMELIZED.
YEP, WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
TO DEGLAZE.
OKAY, SO NOW THE LEAF.
YES, NOW THE LEAF.
THE LUAH LEAF
FROM THE TARO PLANT.
CORRECT.
SOME PEOPLE LIKE IT TO SPINACH,
I DON'T SAY THAT...
SO THIS IS
THE HAWAIIAN COLLARD GREEN.
NICE.
ARE THESE BITTER?
NO, NO, DON'T EAT IT.
BECAUSE WHEN IT'S RAW --
COLOCASIA ESCULENTA,
THAT'S THE NAME OF
THE TARO PLANT,
HAS THESE LIKE,
CRYSTALS IN IT
THAT NEEDS TO BE BROKEN DOWN
WITH HEAT AND MOISTURE
AND TIME.
SO YOU PICK THAT UP
AND YOU EAT IT
YOUR THROAT'S GONNA GET
ALL ITCHY AND CLOSE UP
AND THEN I'M GONNA HAVE
TO PROVIDE MOUTH TO MOUTH
AND YOU DON'T WANT THAT.
SO NOW WE GO IN WITH THE PORK,
IT SITS UP ON TOP OF
THE ITCH-YOUR-THROAT
TARO ROOT LEAF.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS GONNA COOK DOWN
AND NOW WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN?
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT MORE WATER
AND KIND OF LET IT BRAISE DOWN.
THIS IS THE STEW?
THAT'S IT.
NO CARROTS, NO MIREPOIX.
K-I-S-S,
KEEP IT SIMPLE STUPID.
YOU THINK YOU'LL FIT IN THERE?
YEAH!
A LITTLE BIT OF SHOYU.
THE SHOYU IS
THE JAPANESE SOY SAUCE,
BUT IT'S THE SOY SAUCE
THAT YOU USE TYPICALLY
IN HAWAIIAN FOOD?
YES.
ALL RIGHT,
HOW LONG DID THIS COOK?
SLOW AND LOW IS THE WAY TO GO
SO ABOUT 46 HOURS.
DUDE, IT LOOKS LIKE
I'M IN THE WINE COUNTRY,
I'M UP AT SONOMA COUNTY
FOR A MUD MASK.
WHERE ARE YOU?
NOT THAT I'VE EVER HAD
ONE OF THOSE.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE DONE.
YEP.
WE'VE GOT SOME RICE.
AND I'VE GOT
THE "HELLO KITTY" CHOPSTICKS?
HUH, THAT'S WHAT IT IS?
HA-HA, HA-HA-HA.
OH...
THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
THE PORK'S SUPER TENDER.
IT'S VERY RICH,
THERE'S A LOT OF
MOUTH APPEAL TO IT.
CREAMINESS OF THE LUAH...
DUDE, I WOULD DRIVE
FROM THE OTHER SIDE,
I WOULD DRIVE FROM HONOLULU
FOR THIS.
RIGHT ON, RIGHT ON.
DYNAMITE.
SERIOUSLY, OUTSTANDING.
RIGHT ON.
I LOVE THIS DISH,
HE DOES A GOOD JOB
OF COOKING IT,
IT'S VERY COMFORT FOOD.
GOOCH'S PHILOSOPHY
IS YOU GIVE BACK
TO YOUR COMMUNITY
AS MUCH AS YOU'VE BEEN GIVEN.
MARK KNOWS THAT HAWAII'S
AN ISOLATED PLACE
SO YOU GOTTA EAT THE FOODS
THAT ARE GROWN HERE.
(Guy)
LIKE PORK FROM NEARBY
SHINSATO FARMS,
BEEF FROM KUAHIWI RANCH
ON THE BIG ISLAND,
AND EVEN, GET THIS,
SEAWEED FROM
GOOCH'S OWN BACKYARD.
HOW DO YOU GET IT?
YOU GO OUT AND YOU SCOOP IT.
IF IT'S BY THE SHORELINE
YOU JUST GRAB A NET AND...
(Guy)
ALL TO MAKE ANOTHER
TRADITIONAL HAWAIIAN DISH.
I GOT TWO LIMU SALAD.
THAT'S THE BOMB RIGHT THERE.
LIMU SALAD.
LIMU SALAD, YEAH.
IS THIS LIMU?
THAT'S LIMU, SEAWEED.
THIS IS INVASIVE
AND THIS IS CALLED GORILLA.
IT ENCROACHES
ON NATIVE HABITATS...
REALLY?
AND PUSHES THINGS OUT, YEAH.
SO YOU DON'T WANT IT TO EAT IT.
EXACTLY.
IT TASTES A LOT BETTER
AFTER YOU BLANCH IT.
GOOD.
WE'VE GOT A POT OF
ROLLING BOILING WATER
AND WE GOT TO MAKE SURE
TO SALT IT, DROP IT IN.
SO YOU NOTICE
IT'S A DARK COLOR
AND WHEN WE BLANCH IT OFF
FOR A FEW SECONDS
IT'S GONNA TURN TO
A SLIGHTLY MORE LIKE,
GREENER GREEN.
LIKE GREEN BEANS.
YES.
WOW, SO IT GOES THAT FAST?
YEAH, IT GOES THAT FAST,
IN SECONDS.
SO THIS TOOK A LITTLE BIT OF
THE BITTERNESS OUT OF IT?
CORRECT.
WE GOT IT ALL OUT.
WE'RE GONNA SHOCK IT.
SHOCK IT.
THEN WE'LL DRAIN IT
AND LET IT DRY.
BREAK IT DOWN
SO IT'S A LITTLE BIT EASIER
SO WE'RE NOT MUNCHING ON IT
LIKE A... HORSE.
(whinnies)
THAT'S IT.
OKAY.
(Guy whistling)
OKAY, SO NOW WE MAKE
OUR VINAIGRETTE.
SO WE'VE GOT
OUR HAWAIIAN CHILE PEPPERS.
AREN'T THEY CUTE?
THEY ARE, ARE THEY HOT?
THEY'LL KICK YOU IN YOUR...
REALLY?
PUT IN OUR HAWAIIAN CHILE PEPPER
AND GARLIC, HAWAIIAN SALT,
AND GRIND INTO A PASTE.
IS THIS TRADITIONAL HAWAIIAN?
NO, THIS IS JAPANESE.
ONCE WE'VE GOT OUR PASTE
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF
OUR SHERRY VINEGAR...
SHERRY VINEGAR.
YES SIR.
GET IT OUT OF THE GROOVES.
WE TAKE OUR LIMU,
OUR SLICED ONIONS...
A LITTLE CUCUMBER.
WE'LL ADD OUR TOMATOES
FROM WHOLE FARMS.
AND... SHOYU?
A LITTLE BIT OF SHOYU.
NOW WE JUST MIX IT UP.
A LITTLE FINISHING SALT ON TOP.
THIS IS A COMBINATION OF
THREE SALTS FROM THREE
DIFFERENT ISLANDS.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
BRO, IT'S HARD FOR ME TO SAY.
THE SALAD THAT'S MADE OUT OF
THE GORILLA SEAWEED
THAT YOU HARVEST
IN YOUR BACKYARD,
AS FUNKY AS IT IS,
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
FRESH, PALATE CLEANSING.
CAN YOU HEAR THE CRUNCH?
I MEAN,
YOU GOTTA WORK THROUGH THIS.
REALLY NICE.
THERE IS A BURST OF
SALT WATER IN YOUR MOUTH.
A LITTLE BIT OF A BITE TO IT.
STRAIGHT OUT OF THE WATER,
STRAIGHT IN THE BACK DOOR
AND ON YOUR PLATE.
SO WHAT'S NEXT, YOU GOTTA HAVE
A BIG GRAND FINALE?
(Guy)
WHEN WE COME BACK
THE GOOCH DOES NOT DISAPPOINT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
STIR-FRIED BEEF
BUSTING OUT WITH FLAVOR.
WHERE ARE WE AGAIN?
HE'EIA KEA PIER
GENERAL STORE AND DELI.
SEE YOU IN A MINUTE.
(Guy)
WELCOME BACK
TO HE'EIA KEA PIER
GENERAL STORE AND DELI.
THERE YOU GO.
WHO'S SPEAKING HAWAIIAN NOW?
SO WHAT'S NEXT, YOU GOTTA HAVE
A BIG GRAND FINALE?
WHAT DO YOU GOT FOR ME?
NEXT WE'VE GOT MISOYAKI BEEF.
(deli patron)
A LITTLE BIT OF TURKEY FLAVOR,
A LITTLE BIT OF MISO,
IT REMINDS ME OF HOME COOKING.
LET'S GET BUSY.
WHAT CUT DO WE HAVE HERE?
THIS IS A KNUCKLE,
IT COMES OFF OF THE SIRLOIN.
SO A GREAT FLAVOR,
YOU GOTTA CUT IT THE RIGHT WAY
BUT YOU'RE GONNA
GET GREAT TEXTURE
AND GREAT FLAVOR OUT OF THIS
BECAUSE OF THE MARBLING
AND SO FORTH, LET'S DO IT.
WE'RE GONNA MARINATE IT NOW
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF TERIYAKI.
YOU MAKE THE TERIYAKI YOURSELF?
YES WE DO.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF WATER
TO THIN IT OUT, MIX IT UP.
HOW LONGS DOES IT MARINATE FOR?
FOR FOUR TO SIX HOURS
TO OVERNIGHT, SIMPLE.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE, OKAY.
OKAY, NEXT UP WE'RE MAKING
A SAUCE WITH A TAUTI.
SO FIRST WHAT WE DID
IS WE TOOK SAKE AND MIRIN.
REDUCED IT.
RIGHT.
NEXT WE'RE GONNA ADD
SAKE KASU.
SAKE KASU IS WHEN YOU MAKE SAKE,
LIKE ALL THE RICE BRINE,
EVERYTHING IS ALL LEFT OVER.
WHITE MISO.
RED MISO.
AND THIS IS ALL THE SAUCE
THAT'S GONNA GO ON TOP
OF THE MEAT?
THAT'S RIGHT, YEP.
OUR SALTED BLACK BEAN SAUCE.
SO ONCE YOU GOTTA WHISK IT UP,
GET IT NICE AND SMOOTH...
NOW WHICH WAY DO YOU DO IT?
COUNTER "QWOK-WISE."
POINT.
SO WE LET THIS REDUCE DOWN.
YEAH, WE FINISH IT UP WITH KUMA,
TOASTED SESAME SEEDS.
SO ONCE WE GET THIS WOK ON,
FIRE UP,
WE'VE GOT IT RIPPIN' HOT,
HIT IT WITH A LITTLE OIL
RIGHT THERE.
JUST TO GET IT
WHERE IT'S SMOKING?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA OUR BEEF.
SO WE'VE GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF YOUR MISO.
HERE, TASTE IT REAL QUICK.
THIS IS REDUCED.
THE NUTTINESS OF IT,
MMM, YOU GET A LITTLE BIT,
ALMOST LIKE PEANUT BUTTER.
YEAH, BINGO.
THAT'S REAL BIG FLAVOR IN THAT.
AT THIS POINT
WE CAN TURN IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S DELICIOUS, MAN,
LOOK AT THAT, LOOK AT THAT.
YOU REALLY GO TO ALL EXTENT
TO HAVE THE WOK BURNER HERE,
SUPER HOT.
I MEAN, THIS IS
AS HANDMADE AS YOU CAN GET.
I'M IMPRESSED.
THAT'S THE ONLY NICE THING
I'M GONNA SAY TO YOU TODAY.
RIGHT ON.
WE'VE GOT SOME RICE.
CALAMARI SALAD.
FINISH UP,
EH, EH, EH!
OKAY.
HUSH YOU GUYS.
HEY, HI-YEAH!
HELLO KITTY AGAIN, AWESOME.
THIS IS MY STYLE OF FOOD.
I'VE GOTTA WATCH
MY FIGURE, THOUGH,
SO I WATCH THE CARBS.
DUDE, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
KILLIN' YA, HUH?
NO, NO, NO,
I KNOW YOU LIKE IT.
NO, ACTUALLY I DON'T LIKE IT.
I LOVE IT.
YOU'RE UTILIZING
THIS PIECE OF MEAT
SO YOU'VE GOT TEXTURE,
IT'S THIN ENOUGH
YOU CAN EAT A NICE PIECE OF IT
WITHOUT HAVING TO CUT IT,
YOU GET THE SOY, THAT RICHNESS,
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT OF RICE
TO BALANCE IT OUT,
ALL THE COMPONENTS, IT'S AN
ORCHESTRATION OF FLAVORS.
I LOVE IT,
OFF THE HOOK, MAN.
OFF THE DOCK,
THAT'S A NEW ONE.
IT'S RIGHT OFF
THE DOCK, BABY!
DUDE, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
YOU END UP IN WAIKIKI,
YOU SAY, "I WANT TO BREAK OUT
AND FIND SOMETHING GREAT,"
IT'S A 25-MINUTE DRIVE
OVER HERE,
COME THROUGH THE TUNNELS,
END UP YOU'RE IN PARADISE
RIGHT ON THE WATER,
A COOL, LITTLE PIER,
ALL LOCALS,
A BUNCH OF BOATS
AND FOOD LIKE THIS,
YOU KNOCKED IT OUT, MAN,
CONGRATULATIONS.
MAHALO.
(Guy)
UP NEXT...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
(Guy)
WE'RE HEADED
TO CHICAGO, ILLINOIS...
YOU'RE LIKE A BLACKJACK DEALER
AT THE FLAVOR TOWN CASINO.
(Guy)
FOR A KILLER SICILIAN SPECIALTY.
COOK UP A PIZZA, MADE A SANDWICH
AND HAD A BABY.
BOOM,
YOU'VE GOT YOUR SCHIACCIATA.
SO I'LL TELL YOU SOMETHING
THAT HAPPENS TO ME
ALL THE TIME.
FRIENDS WILL CALL ME AND SAY,
"HEY GUY, I'M STUCK
AT THIS AIRPORT ON A LAYOVER
"YOU GOT ANY "TRIPLE D" JOINTS
THAT ARE CLOSE BY?"
WELL I'VE GOT ONE FOR YA.
I'M ABOUT A 15-MINUTE CAB RIDE
FROM CHICAGO O'HARE
AND I'M HERE
ON NORTH HARLEM AVENUE
TO CHECK OUT
SOME REAL-DEAL ITALIAN.
THIS IS REX ITALIAN FOODS.
MUFFALELLA PIE.
THIS IS GENUINE ITALIAN FOOD.
TORTELLINI SALAD.
THE BEST ITALIAN FOOD
I'VE EVER HAD.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE IN ITALY
WHEN YOU COME IN HERE.
(Guy)
FROM THE SCRATCH-MADE FOOD
PINA PINELLO GREW UP ON
BACK IN SICILY
TO THE LOOK AND FEEL OF
AN ITALIAN HOME.
EVERYBODY THAT COMES
INTO THE STORE IS LIKE,
MY FRIEND.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR SOMETHING
THAT'S HOMEMADE, MADE WITH LOVE,
THEN YOU'VE DEFINITELY FOUND
THE RIGHT PLACE.
(Guy)
THAT'S ANTHONY PINELLO
WHO STARTED OUT
MAKING DELIVERIES
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
I'VE GOT NINE SAUSAGES
GOING UP.
(Guy)
NOW HE'S CRANKING OUT
HIS MOM'S FAMILY RECIPES
AND ROLLING OUT
HIS OWN CREATIONS
LIKE THIS BAD BOY.
SICILIAN SCHIACCIATA.
IT'S LIKE
THIS GREAT BOLD AMAZINGNESS.
FROM A PIZZA,
MADE A SANDWICH,
HAD A BABY,
BOOM, YOU'VE GOT
YOUR SCHIACCIATA.
SCHIACCIATAS?
SCHIACCIATA,
IT MEANS FLATTENED IN ITALIAN.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
SO HERE WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR WET INGREDIENTS
FOR OUR DOUGH.
OKAY, WE PUT OUR SALT
AND OUR SUGAR
AND THEN WE PUT
OUR FRESH YEAST.
A BUNCH OF IT.
MM-HMM.
WE HAVE OUR WATER,
WE ADD HALF TO THIS BOWL...
HALF TO THE OTHER
TO LET THAT DISSOLVE.
EXACTLY, WHISK IT.
IT SMELLS GREAT.
COMBINE THOSE.
THEN WE ADD
OUR ITALIAN OLIVE OIL.
THAT'S THE SECRET INGREDIENT.
SO ALL THIS GOES TOGETHER
INTO THE MIXER WITH THE FLOUR?
RIGHT.
SO NOW LET'S MAKE THE DOUGH?
DURHAM FLOUR,
HIGH GLUTEN FLOUR.
POTATO GRANULES,
ALSO KNOWN AS POTATO FLOUR.
REALLY?
YEAH, DON'T ASK ME
WHY WE USE IT,
IT'S JUST MY NONA'S RECIPE.
AND YOU DON'T QUESTION NONA,
JUST GO WITH IT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND NOW WE'LL ADD
THE WET INGREDIENTS.
WE MIXED IT UP,
IT HAD A CHANCE TO RISE.
THEN WE'LL PUNCH IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
NOW WE'LL PORTION IT OUT.
WE USE ABOUT THREE POUNDS
FOR ONE SCHIACCIATA.
IT SMELLS GREAT,
THAT FRESH YEAST.
SO WE PUT
A LITTLE FLOUR IN HERE,
PUT A LITTLE SEMOLINA FLOUR
INTO OUR PAN, TOO.
IT KEEPS IT FROM STICKING.
YEAH.
JUST ONCE THROUGH THE TOP,
ONCE THROUGH THE BOTTOM.
THAT'S IT.
LAY IT OUT,
PULL IT TO THE CORNERS.
THAT'S IT.
ARE WE GONNA LET THIS PROOF
BEFORE WE TOP IT?
YEAH, WE LET IT RISE
A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY, DOUGH'S OUT.
SO WE START BUILDING
OUR SCHIACCIATA.
TAKE THE MOZZARELLA...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU DON'T DO IT ON BOTH SIDES?
NO, WHAT YOU DO,
WE'RE GONNA CLOSE IT UP.
IT'S A GIANT CALZONE?
THAT'S A GOOD WAY TO PUT IT.
IT'S A PIZZA STRUDEL, BASICALLY.
THIS IS ITALIAN
PROSCIUTTO COTTO.
COOKED PROSCIUTTO.
COOKED PROSCIUTTO, RIGHT.
EVERY ONE KNOWS THE DRIED,
CURED PROSCIUTTO,
THAT'S THE ONE
THAT'S KIND OF LIKE
ITS MORE FAMOUS COUSIN.
IN THE STATES WE CALL THAT HAM.
RIGHT.
OKAY, THEN AFTER THAT
WE PUT THE PEPPERONI DOWN.
YOU'RE LIKE A BLACKJACK DEALER
AT THE FLAVOR TOWN CASINO.
YEAH, RIGHT.
AND THEN SOME FRIED PEPPERS.
YOU FRIED 'EM?
HM-MMM, WE USE A DEEP FRYER.
IT GIVES A LITTLE TEXTURE
AND THEN WE ADD...
MORE CHEESE.
MORE CHEESE, YEAH.
YOU JUST PUT IT TO BED.
JUST FOLD IT OVER, YEP.
PRESS THE EDGES OVER HERE.
THIS IS LIKE,
STROMBOLI GONE WILD.
THEN WE PUT A LITTLE EGG WASH,
WE THROW A LITTLE MORE
SEMOLINA FLOUR ON TOP
AND THAT'S IT.
THEN WE GO STRAIGHT
TO THE OVEN WITH IT.
WHAT TEMP?
450, FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES.
FOR 20 MINUTES?
YEAH.
OKAY, SO NOW IT'S OUT OF
THE OVEN, IT'S COOLED DOWN.
RIGHT.
NOW FOR SERVICE?
WE TAKE IT OUT OF THE PAN.
WE'RE GONNA CUT IT
IN OUR EIGHT STRIPS.
HOLY HAM AND CHEESE.
THEN THOSE STRIPS INDIVIDUALLY
GET TOSSED ON THE PANINI GRILL
TO GIVE IT THE GRILL MARKS
AND WARM EVERYTHING
ELSE UP INSIDE.
I CAN HEAR THE SNAP, CRACKLE...
YEAH, YOU CAN HEAR THE SIZZLING.
IT'S READY TO COME OFF
THE PANINI PRESS.
YOU JUST CUT THAT IN HALF,
THERE YOU GO.
ITALIAN HAM AND CHEESE
WITH SOME PEPPERS
AND SOME PEPPERONI.
YEAH.
MMM, YOU'VE GOT
THAT SEMOLINA FLOUR
ON THE OUTSIDE
WHICH GIVES THAT NICE,
LITTLE, CRUSTY TEXTURE.
THE PEPPERONI AND THE HAM
AND THE PEPPERS
INFUSE THAT FLAVOR
INTO THE DOUGH.
MMM, PROSCIUTTO COTTO
IS NICE AND TENDER
AND NOT TOO SALTY.
YOU KNOW, THE FRIED PEPPERS
COMING IN THERE.
I MEAN, MMM, EXCELLENT.
IT'S LIKE A REAL-DEAL
ITALIAN HAM AND CHEESE.
A HAM AND CHEESE,
SICILIAN-STYLE.
SICILIAN SCHIACCIATA.
YOU CAN'T DESCRIBE IT.
YOU HAVE TO COME IN HERE
AND EXPERIENCE IT FOR YOURSELF.
I'M ALWAYS TORN
OF WHAT TO GET,
COLD FOOD, SALADS,
HOT FOOD,
EVEN STUFF TO TAKE HOME
AND MAKE YOURSELF.
I ACTUALLY GREW UP WITH A LOT OF
THE PRODUCTS THEY SALE
AND A LOT OF IT
YOU CAN'T FIND ANYWHERE.
I NEVER KNEW
WHERE MY NONY GOT IT.
IT'S AWESOME THAT I HAVE
THE STUFF AVAILABLE TO ME.
THE PASSION THAT THE EMPLOYEES
HAVE FOR THE FOOD
GOES RIGHT INTO THE FOOD.
AND TO ME
THAT MAKES IT GREAT,
NO MATTER WHAT YOU HAVE.
SICILIAN SCHIACCIATA.
NOW ON THE CAMERA, US COME HERE.
CAN I KISS YOU?
OH BOY, I KNEW THIS...
YOU GUYS GOTTA COME DOWN HERE
AND SEE THEM.
(Guy)
COMING UP...
OKAY, LET'S START THIS BREAD.
(Guy)
WE'RE HEADED DOWN
TO HERNANDO, MISSISSIPPI...
THIS SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
(Guy)
FOR A SECRET CELLAR RESTAURANT
GOING BANANAS ON DESSERT,
AND YOU KNOW
THAT'S A GOOD THING.
THAT IS DECADENT.
SO HERE I AM
IN HERNANDO, MISSISSIPPI,
ABOUT TEN MILES
FROM THE TENNESSEE,
MISSISSIPPI BORDER.
NOW RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET
FROM THE COURTHOUSE
IS A LITTLE JOINT
THAT'S UNDERGROUND
AND SERVING UP
SCRATCH-MADE COMFORT FOOD.
YOU GOTTA CHECK IT OUT,
THIS IS MEMPHIS ST. CAFE.
CATFISH UP.
IT'S WONDERFUL,
LIGHT AND FLAKY.
REUBEN IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S THE BEST
I'VE EVER HAD.
IS THIS TYPICAL FARE?
NO, I WOULD DESCRIBE IT
AS A SURPRISE IN HERNANDO.
(Guy)
BECAUSE CHRIS AND NATALIE LEE
ARE BRINGING
AN INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE
TO SMALL TOWN,
M-I-S-S-I-S-S-I-P-P-I.
WHERE DID YOU GO TO SCHOOL?
I GRADUATED FROM LE CORDON BLEU
IN LONDON.
NICE.
(Guy)
BUT AT HIS JOINT
HE'S KEEPING IT REAL.
(female patron)
EVERYBODY KNOWS EVERYBODY
AND CHRIS KNOWS
WHAT WE LIKE.
(Guy)
AND WHAT THEY DIG
IS SOUTHERN COMFORT DISHES
LIKE SHRIMP AND GRITS
OR A CRAZY DESSERT CONCOCTION
THAT'S DOWN RIGHT BANANAS.
THE WHOLE THING
IS JUST DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE MAKING
A BANANA NUT BREAD FRENCH TOAST.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S START THIS BREAD.
FIRST THING,
ADD THE BUTTER INTO THE BOWL.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SUGAR.
CREAM THE BUTTER
AND THE SUGAR.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD THE EGGS.
SCRAPE THAT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
WE'LL GET THAT GOING.
THAT POOR LITTLE MIXER'S
ABOUT SEEN ITS LAST DAY, HUH?
IT'S GOT A MOTOR ON IT
AS STRONG AS A CAMARO
OUT THERE, MAN.
SO WE JUST CREAM
THAT TOGETHER A LITTLE BIT.
1/2 TEASPOON OF KOSHER SALT.
THAT'S TWO TEASPOONS OF
BAKING SODA.
FOUR CUPS FLOUR.
NOW WE GET SIX VERY RIPE BANANAS
AND WE MASH 'EM.
YOU WANT KIND OF
A CHUNKY MASH.
RIGHT, SO THAT'S THE REASON
WE'RE NOT PUTTING 'EM
IN THE MIXER
BECAUSE IT WOULD JUST
CREAM 'EM OUT.
I LIKE A LITTLE CHUNK IN THERE.
SO WE'RE GONNA ADD PECANS IN,
ROASTED AND SALTED, GOT IT?
THEN WE PUT THE BANANAS IN.
AND WE KIND OF DO THIS
A LITTLE BIT SLOWER.
JUST ENOUGH
TO INCORPORATE IT,
NOT CREAM IT OUT,
AND YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUR BAKING DISH
AND WE'RE GONNA SPRAY IT DOWN.
POUR YOUR MIXTURE IN.
IT'S GONNA COOK OFF AT 325
FOR ABOUT 1 HOUR, 15 MINUTES.
OKAY, BREAD'S DONE.
SO HERE WE'LL MAKE OUR EGG WASH
FOR THE FRENCH TOAST.
EGGS,
WHIP UP THE EGGS,
ADD A LITTLE WHOLE MILK,
A LITTLE BIT OF CINNAMON.
YOU WANT ME
TO POP THIS OUT?
YES SIR.
MMM, SMELL THAT.
WE'LL CUT A SLICE,
A NICE SLICE HERE,
PUT THAT IN THERE,
LET IT SIT FOR A SECOND,
SOAK IT UP,
GET SOME WHOLE BUTTER
IN THE PAN,
LET THIS MELT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
RIGHT THERE, YOU'RE STARTING TO
SEE THE FOAM ON THE TOP OF
THE BUTTER.
THEN WE PUT IT DOWN IN THERE.
LET THAT GO FOR JUST A SECOND.
OKAY.
OVER HERE, WE'RE GONNA GET
OUR BANANA READY FOR
THE FOSTERS.
DID YOU FLIP THAT YET, CHEF?
I HAVE NOT.
I THINK IT'S ABOUT READY.
THERE YOU GO.
GORGEOUS.
AND I'M GONNA THROW IT
IN THE OVEN
THAT WAY THE OUTSIDE EDGE
WILL FEEL JUST LIKE
THE BOTTOM WILL.
GOT ANOTHER SKILLET,
A LITTLE BUTTER IN THERE.
WE'VE GOT OUR BANANA.
ALL OF THIS
FOR ONE DESSERT.
ONE DESSERT.
BANANAS ARE COOKING,
GONNA ADD SOME BROWN SUGAR,
LET THAT MELT DOWN A LITTLE BIT
WITH THE BANANA.
MAKING A LITTLE CARAMEL THERE.
HIT IT WITH A SHOT OF COGNAC.
VERY NICE.
AND THEN RIGHT AT THE END...
HEAVY CREAM.
HEAVY CREAM JUST TO KIND OF
BRING IT ALL TOGETHER.
FRENCH TOAST,
PUT IT IN THE BOWL.
NOW YOU'VE GOT YOUR BANANAS
WITH THE SAUCE, STACK IT UP.
PUT A LITTLE ICE CREAM
ON TOP --
IT'S VANILLA BEAN
AND FRENCH GINGER,
TWO SCOOPS.
WITH FRENCH TOAST
YOU ALWAYS GOTTA HAVE
A LITTLE POWDERED SUGAR ON TOP,
YOU WANT TO GET A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYTHING TOGETHER.
YOU'VE GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
THE CRUNCHY TEXTURE OF
THE FRENCH TOAST,
THEN YOU GET THOSE PECANS
INSIDE OF THERE.
TRUE BANANA FLAVOR,
AND IF YOU DIDN'T GET
ENOUGH BANANA FLAVOR FROM THAT
YOU GET THE MOAT-O-BANANA.
THAT ICE CREAM
WITH THE LITTLE HINT OF
THE GINGER SETS ANOTHER BALANCE.
IT'S A PACKAGED DEAL, MAN.
THAT IS DECADENT.
FRENCH TOAST.
I DO NOT LIKE TO SHARE IT.
WHAT KILLS ME
ABOUT THE WAY YOU DO STUFF
IS EVERYTHING HAS TO BE DONE
TO LIKE, THE NEXT LEVEL,
YOU MAKE THE BANANA BREAD,
YOU MAKE THE ICE CREAM.
IF I GAVE YOU A CHANCE
IN A SMALL JUNGLE
YOU'D PROBABLY GROW THE BANANAS.
GO STRAIGHT TO GUATEMALA.
YEP, ON HIS WAY.
NICE JOB, BROTHER,
THANK YOU.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR TOWN ROAD TRIP.
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS
AND DIVES."
SO GO AHEAD WITH WHATEVER ELSE
YOU WERE DOING.
ALL RIGHT, SO NEXT UP
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME...
WAIT A MINUTE,
YOU CAN'T STAND IN FRONT OF ME.
I MEAN, I AM GONNA BE INVOLVED
IN MY OWN SHOW, THANK YOU.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE?