HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
TAKE US FOR A RIDE.
IT'S ALL ABOUT
THE PUBS AND THE GRUB.
A LITTLE TRASHY, A LITTLE
CLASSY. THAT'S AWESOME.
YEAH.
GOT IT.
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
I'M STANDING BACK
FOR THIS.
A SECOND-GENERATION JOINT...
OHH!
LEADING WITH A CLASSIC...
THAT'LL TAKE YOU BACK.
THAT'S HOME
FROM SCHOOL, MAN.
AND CLOSING WITH A SANDWICH...
YOU GUYS ARE SERIOUS.
RIPPING OFF ALL MY BEST LINES.
OUT OF BOUNDS, OFF THE HOOK,
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR,
CALL A NEIGHBOR,
AND GET A TICKET.
IN KILL DEVIL HILLS,
NORTH CAROLINA...
WHAT'S IN IT?
A TRULY UNIQUE BREWHOUSE
POWERED BY ITS OWN
WIND TURBINE ON PREMISES.
GOING LOW COUNTRY
WITH SERIOUS SHRIMP AND GRITS.
IF I LIVED IN TOWN,
YOU'D SEE ME ONCE A WEEK.
AND IN
CRANSTON, RHODE ISLAND...
A COUPLE CASTANETS,
AND YOU COULD SNAP THAT OUT.
A SIDEWALK CAFé...
COME ON DOWN AND GET
A LITTLE SURPRISE.
PACKING IN ALL THE FLAVORS...
EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL
AT THIS POINT.
OF THE OCEAN STATE.
I'D EAT THIS
ALL DAY LONG.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE RIGHT NOW
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
♪♪
SO I'M HERE IN THE CENTRAL WEST
END AREA OF ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
NOW THIS AREA
WAS REALLY BUILT UP
DURING THE TURN OF THE CENTURY
AND THE WORLD'S FAIR,
SO IT'S GOT TONS OF HISTORY.
NOW IT'S GOT REALLY COOL
SHOPS AND RESTAURANTS
LIKE THIS JOINT, WHERE THEY GOT
AN OLD-SCHOOL PUB MENU
BUT A NEW-SCHOOL, SCRATCH-MADE,
FARM-TO-TABLE ATTITUDE.
THIS IS DRESSEL'S PUBLIC HOUSE.
ALL RIGHT,
WE GOT MUSSELS UP.
EXTREMELY FRESH FOOD HERE.
HERE WE ARE--
THE LAMB BURGER.
IT FEELS LIKE I'M IN
SOME OLD-SCHOOL PUB.
ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S THE CHARM. IT'S THE PEOPLE.
THE FOOD--THE FOOD'S AMAZING.
HOW YOU DOING, FELLAS?
BEN'S DONE SUCH A GREAT JOB
OF DOING LOCAL THINGS,
WHETHER IT'S PORK
OR BEEF.
IT'S KIND OF, UH, NICE TO SEE
THAT HAPPENING RIGHT NOW.
THE CAT RIDING
THE FARM-TO-TABLE WAVE
IS BEN DRESSEL,
WHOSE DAD TURNED THIS FORMER
ROCK 'N' ROLL BAR
INTO A PUB IN 1980.
(Guy) HOW DO YOU
DESCRIBE THIS JOINT?
(Ben) SLOW FOOD AND TRYING TO
SOURCE INGREDIENTS LOCALLY
AND MAKE ALL THAT WORK,
SO THAT WHEN PEOPLE DO SHOW UP,
THEY'RE LIKE, "HEY, IT'S A PUB,
RIGHT? THIS IS A PUB."
AND I'M LIKE,
"WELL, YEAH, IT'S A PUB."
BUT YOU GET
THE REAL-DEAL FOOD.
YEAH.
THAT'S WHERE CHEF MIKE MILLER
COMES INTO PLAY.
THIS IS KIND OF
OUR APPROACH TO FOOD.
IT'S A LITTLE LOWBROW,
A LITTLE HIGHBROW--
WE LIKE TO CALL IT A LITTLE
TRASHY, A LITTLE CLASSY.
A LITTLE TRASHY, A LITTLE
CLASSY. THAT'S AWESOME.
YEAH.
GRILLED CHEESE TOMATO BISQUE UP.
(woman) THIS IS ACTUALLY
A COUPLE STEPS UP
FROM MOM'S GRILLED CHEESE
AND TOMATO SOUP.
IT'S WONDERFUL.
WHEN YOU WERE A KID,
DID YOU HAVE
GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH
AND TOMATO SOUP? AH!
THAT'S WHAT IT'S
ALL ABOUT.
ALL RIGHT, SO FIRST,
WE START OFF WITH THE BISQUE.
YEP.
A LITTLE BIT OF BLENDED OIL,
SIX YELLOW ONIONS SLICED...
OKAY.
AND THEN ABOUT
20 CLOVES OF GARLIC.
SWEAT THIS DOWN, PROBABLY
ABOUT FIVE OR TEN MINUTES.
OKAY.
WE'RE GONNA ADD ABOUT
A QUART OF ARBORIO RICE.
THIS IS A CLASSIC
THICKENER OF BISQUE.
OKAY.
JUST WANT TO GET
A NICE TOAST ON THE RICE.
JUST LIKE WE'RE
MAKING RISOTTO.
EXACTLY.
NOW WE HIT IT WITH
SAN MARZANO TOMATOES?
ABSOLUTELY.
STANDING BACK FOR THIS.
TRYING NOT TO MAKE
A HUGE MESS WITH THIS.
REALLY?
YOU'RE DOING AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT, LIQUID
IN THE FORM OF VEGETABLE STOCK.
AND YOU GUYS MADE THIS?
WE DID.
THEN HIT IT WITH
THE IMMERSION BLENDER.
AND, UH, WE'RE GONNA
MAKE A LOT OF NOISE.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW THIS
FINISHES COOKING OUT
A LITTLE BIT FURTHER.
YES.
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF CREAM TO ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF FAT TO IT.
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER,
AND OUR SOUP IS NOW READY TO GO.
LET'S MAKE
A GRILLED CHEESE SANDWICH.
WHO MAKES THE BREAD?
COMPANION BAKERY. WE GET IT
EVERY DAY, SO IT'S SUPER FRESH.
OKAY.
WE LIKE IT TO BE
PRETTY RIDICULOUSLY THICK.
OH, WHOA, WHOA.
AND THIS GOES DIRECTLY
ONTO THE FLATTOP.
TWO SLICES PER SIDE
OF AMERICAN CHEESE,
OUR 3-CHEESE BLEND--
PROVEL, GRUYèRE, AND SWISS.
SO SWEET AND SHARP.
ABSOLUTELY.
WE ADD A LITTLE CLASSY ELEMENT,
WHICH IS THE TRUFFLE OIL.
YOU START IT OFF, BUILD
THE CRUST ON THE OUTSIDE,
THROW IT ON A SHEET TRAY,
INTO THE OVEN,
BURN IT OFF,
STICK 'EM TOGETHER.
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK AT THAT. SO NICE
AND CRISPY ON THE BOTTOM.
NOT BROWNED ON THE TOP,
SO WHEN YOU STICK IT TOGETHER,
THE MAGIC HAPPENS.
THERE IT IS.
NICELY DONE.
OH, YOU'RE JUST TEASING ME WITH
THAT AMOUNT OF TOMATO BISQUE.
LOOK AT THE SIZE
OF THIS THING.
VERY NICE TOUCH
WITH THE TRUFFLE OIL.
LOCALLY MADE BREAD, AND ENOUGH
CHEESE TO SINK A SHIP.
FANTASTIC.
DELICIOUS BISQUE.
THAT'S THE KEY, THOUGH,
RIGHT THERE, IS THE DUNK.
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'LL TAKE YOU BACK.
MMM.
THAT'S HOME FROM SCHOOL, MAN.
WELL DONE.
THANKS A LOT.
TRUFFLE GRILLED CHEESE
WITH OUR TOMATO BISQUE.
CRISPY BREAD, LIKE, REALLY
DRIPPY, CHEESY, YUMMY GOODNESS
WITH THE CREAMY BISQUE,
AND IT'S AWESOME.
IF THAT WAS A WORD,
IT'S, LIKE, THAT LONG.
THAT IS A MOUTHFUL,
ALL SERVED UP
IN A CLASSIC PUB ATMOSPHERE
THAT'S STEEPED
IN FAMILY HISTORY.
YOUR GREAT-GRANDPARENTS
IMMIGRATED FROM...
FROM WALES.
WALES
TO THE UNITED STATES.
THAT'S CORRECT.
YOUR DAD GOES
BACK TO WALES,
KIND OF FINDS HIS--
FINDS HIS ROOTS.
AND A COUPLE OF RECIPES,
INCLUDING A TRADITIONAL WELSH
CHEESE SAUCE CALLED RAREBIT,
SERVED NEXT TO ONE
OF MY ALL-TIME WEAKNESSES,
A HOMEMADE PRETZEL.
WE HAVE A DRESSEL'S PRETZEL
WITH THE RAREBIT.
(man) THE RAREBIT--IT'S
A REALLY NICE CHEESE SAUCE.
THE GREATEST THING
YOU CAN DO WITH A PRETZEL
IS MAKE IT REALLY FRESH.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
THE HOUSE PRETZEL.
WHO'S MAKING THE DOUGH?
VITALE'S BAKERY.
THEY'RE LOCATED
ON THE HILL.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA
ROLL THIS GUY OUT.
TWO TUBES...
OKAY.
AND THEN
WE'LL BRAID THEM.
OH, DOUBLE DUTCH.
YEAH. EACH OF THESE
GET CUT INTO A THIRD.
WHAT WE HAVE IS JUST A BARELY
SIMMERING HOTEL PAN OF WATER.
WE WANT TO SEASON IT
WITH SALT,
AND THEN WE ADD
BAKING POWDER.
YEP.
GIVES US THE NICE LITTLE CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE.
THE SHINY, THE CHEW TEXTURE
THAT'S ASSOCIATED
WITH A SOFT PRETZEL.
AND THEN THESE GO IN TO PROOF
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE
AND A HALF, TWO MINUTES.
OKAY.
THESE GUYS ARE
ABOUT READY.
TRANSFER THEM
TO A FLOURED SHEET TRAY.
BAKE 'EM OFF.
RIGHT BEFORE THEY FINISH,
BRUSH 'EM, SALT 'EM,
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
WE'LL BRUSH 'EM WITH
BUTTER AND SEA SALT,
AND THEY'RE
READY TO GO.
RIGHT TO THE OVEN NOW.
ABSOLUTELY.
COOL.
MAKE THE RAREBIT SAUCE?
YEAH, LET'S DO IT.
WE'RE MAKING
GIGANTIC FONDUE.
ABSOLUTELY.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH A ROUX.
OKAY.
WE HAVE A POUND
OF BUTTER.
WE'RE GONNA MELT THAT DOWN,
ADD ABOUT A QUART OF FLOUR.
COOK THE FLOUR OUT,
BUT NOT PUTTING ANY COLOR.
SURE.
2 QUARTS OF WATER,
2 QUARTS OF HEAVY CREAM,
AND THEN WOULD YOU MIND
PASSING ME THAT 4 QUART OF BEER?
OH, NICE.
THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF HOT SAUCE.
AS YOU SHOULD.
WORCESTERSHIRE.
AND THEN SOME DIJON.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE'RE AT A BOIL.
YEP.
NOW WE START
TO SPRINKLE THE CHEESE?
YEP, THIS IS
A SHARP CHEDDAR CHEESE.
AS LONG AS IT'S
DISSOLVING INTO IT,
WE'RE ADDING IT
AT THE RIGHT TEMPO.
ABSOLUTELY.
AWESOME.
AND IT MAKES
A HUGE DIFFERENCE
WHEN YOU GET THAT
NICE SILKY TEXTURE.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
NOW WE'RE GONNA BURR MIX IT.
OKAY.
AND IT'S DONE.
WE'RE READY TO SERVE.
AW, SEE, LOOK AT THAT
CRUST THAT'S ON IT.
YOU DIP THAT
IN A LITTLE OF THE RAREBIT.
MMM.
THE CRUST,
THE CHEW, THE SALT,
AND THEN THE DIP.
MMM.
THE RAREBIT'S GOT A NICE BITE
TO IT--THAT SHARP CHEDDAR.
LITTLE UNDERTONES
OF THAT WORCESTERSHIRE
AND A LITTLE HOT SAUCE,
YOU KNOW, JUST THAT LITTLE BITE.
MMM. THAT'S CRAZY.
THANK YOU.
HANGING OUT WITH YOU,
MIKE, IS TROUBLE.
THE PRETZELS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE SANDWICH IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE TOMATO BISQUE
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
WE'RE HANGING OUT AT DRESSEL'S
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
IT'S GONNA BE BIG.
PORCHETTA "LOUIE."
LUCKY I HAVE THAT,
UH, RETRACTABLE JAW.
LIKE AN ANACONDA?
THANK YOU.
WELCOME BACK.
TRIPLE "D" HANGING OUT
IN THE CENTRAL WEST END
OF ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
AT DRESSEL'S PUBLIC HOUSE
WITH MY BUDDY MIKE.
WHAT'S UP NEXT,
MY BROTHER?
PORCHETTA SANDWICH.
BUT NOT PORCHETTA REGULAR,
PORCHETTA WITH--
PORCHETTA "LOUIE,"
WITH A PORK BUTT.
INTERESTING. YOU DON'T OFTEN SEE
PORCHETTA MADE OUT OF PORK BUTT.
LOCAL PORK?
IT IS.
IT COMES WITH THE BONE.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE THE BONE OUT.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO A VERY NICE JOB,
FILLETED THIS OUT,
AND THAT'S ABOUT AS PERFECT
AS YOU CAN GET IT.
TAKE US FOR A RIDE.
OKAY, SO WE'RE GONNA START WITH
SOME EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
CHOPPED GARLIC,
THREE DIFFERENT
HERBS IN HERE--
WE HAVE ROSEMARY,
PARSLEY, AND SAGE.
BOUNTY OF THE COUNTY
THERE, HUH?
AND WE'RE GONNA SEASON IT
PRETTY GENEROUSLY WITH SALT.
WE HAVE, UH,
BLACK PEPPER HERE.
OOH, THIS IS A TASTE.
IT'S FRESHLY GRATED
LEMON ZEST,
SO IT GIVES YOU THAT NICE CITRUS
FLAVOR WITHOUT THE ACID--
WITHOUT THE ACID, YEP.
ACID, EXACTLY, AND THEN WE LIKE
A LITTLE BIT OR ORANGE AS WELL.
DUDE, I'M DIGGING
THE RECIPE.
ADD A LITTLE HEAT
WITH SOME CHILI FLAKE,
AND FINALLY, WE'RE GONNA
USE SOME FENNEL SEED.
NOW WE'RE READY
TO ROLL IT UP.
LOOK AT THIS.
DUDE, YOU GUYS
ARE SERIOUS.
AND THEN YOU WANT TO KEEP
YOUR FAT CAP UP ON TOP.
SO WHEN WE COOK,
FAT DRIPS DOWN.
THIS WILL BE WHERE WE REALLY
SEE HIS, UH, TRUE MERIT.
THIS IS NOT
HIS FIRST RODEO.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
SO THIS WILL
GIVE US A CHANCE
TO REALLY BUILD
A NICE CRUNCHY EXTERIOR.
I'LL SEASON IT WITH
SALT AND PEPPER,
AND WE'RE GOOD TO GO.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THE PORCHETTA PORK BUTT
COOKS OFF AT 350
FOR 3 TO 4 HOURS.
REMEMBER "A CHRISTMAS STORY"
WHEN THE TURKEY WOULD COME OUT
AND THE DAD
WOULD DO THE PICKING?
BE VERY CAREFUL. YOU DON'T WANT
ANYBODY CHEWING ON THE STRING.
REALLY NICE,
BEAUTIFUL CRUST.
LET ME JUST TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
THERE YOU GO.
TAKE A LOOKY-LOO
AT THAT, HUH?
NOW WHAT IS THAT
OVER THERE?
THAT'S OUR FLATTOP, GUY.
MMM.
HOW IS IT?
THE HERBS, THE GARLIC,
A LITTLE OF THE RED
CHILI FLAKE, OHH!
SO WE GOT IT SLICED.
YES.
NOW WHAT?
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THE SANDWICH.
A LITTLE BIT OF BLENDED OIL,
SOME GARLIC,
SOME BLANCHED RAPINI.
VERY NICE.
CHILI FLAKE.
SWEAT THAT GARLIC DOWN,
AND NOW WE DEGLAZE.
BEER,
AND NOW
WE ADD THE MEAT.
THIS IS FOR YOU.
A LITTLE PEPPERONCINI.
(Mike) 3-CHEESE BLEND,
SO YOU HAVE PROVEL, GRUYèRE,
AND SWISS CHEESE IN HERE.
WE'RE JUST GONNA COVER IT
AND LET IT STEAM.
OKAY.
SO THE CHEESE IS MELTED, AND
THEN WE'LL BE READY TO PLATE,
AND THEN WE'RE JUST
GONNA PILE IT ON.
THERE YOU GO--
PORCHETTA "LOUIE."
LUCKY I HAVE THAT,
UH, RETRACTABLE JAW.
LIKE AN ANACONDA?
THANK YOU.
OH, DUDE.
PRETTY TASTY?
OH, MMM.
THE PORCHETTA IS SO SUPER
TENDER, IT'S OUT OF BOUNDS.
AND THEN YOU GET THIS BALANCE
AND THE COMPLEXITIES.
THAT ONE ITEM
IS ALL YOU NEED.
YOU CAN TEAR UP
THE REST OF THE MENU.
I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
THAT WOULD BE A TRIPLE "D"
HALL OF FAME SANDWICH.
THAT IS OUTSTANDING,
OUT OF BOUNDS,
OFF THE HOOK,
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR,
CALL A NEIGHBOR,
AND GET A TICKET.
AWESOME.
PORCHETTA "LOUIE."
OH, THAT'S
A BEAUTIFUL SANDWICH.
WONDERFUL BLEND
OF PORK AND THE PROVEL
AND THE PEPPERONCINIS--
FANTASTIC.
THE HOUSE SAUSAGE UP.
(man) FOOD'S GREAT.
THE ATMOSPHERE IS FUN.
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THE CLASSICS,
AND THAT'S
WHAT THIS PUB IS.
AND THEN YOU THREE ARE HERE,
KIND OF LIKE "CHEERS."
OF COURSE,
YES, EXACTLY.
EVERYBODY KNOWS
YOUR NAME, RIGHT?
IT'S GUY.
IT'S NOT THAT TOUGH.
(all laughing)
UP NEXT...
WHAT ARE WE
STARTING WITH?
WE'RE HEADED
TO THE O.B.X., BABY--
KILL DEVIL HILLS,
NORTH CAROLINA...
LOVE IT.
FOR A RESTAURANT/BREWHOUSE...
WHAT'S BETTER--
THE BEER OR THE FOOD?
GOING REAL DEAL...
TOUGH QUESTION, HUH?
WITH A SOUTHERN STAPLE.
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY
SHOULD BE THINKING
ABOUT THEIR CARBON FOOTPRINT.
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS,
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
FARM-TO-TABLE, SUSTAINABILITY,
ENERGY CONSUMPTION.
SO I'M HERE ON THE COAST
OF NORTH CAROLINA
IN KILL DEVIL HILLS TO VISIT
A RESTAURANT BREW PUB
THAT'S POWERED BY ITS OWN
WIND TURBINE ON PREMISES.
THIS IS
OUTER BANKS BREWING STATION.
CEVICHE'S UP.
WHAT I LOVE IS WE HAVE
ALL THIS FRESH SEAFOOD
COMING RIGHT OFF OUR BANKS.
(man) FRESH, LOCAL INGREDIENTS
MAKE ALL THE DIFFERENCE,
AND THAT'S WHAT
THEY SPECIALIZE IN.
IT WAS A DREAM
THAT STARTED LIKE A FAIRY TALE
WITH ERIC REECE
AND AUBREY DAVIS
LONG AGO ON A FARAWAY BEACH.
WE MET
IN PEACE CORPS, YEAH.
PEACE CORPS BACK
IN THE EARLY '90s.
TIME OUT.
TIME OUT. TIME OUT.
THERE'S A CURVEBALL.
THAT'S HOW THIS STARTS
IS WITH THE PEACE CORPS?
YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED?
A LOT OF CHEAP
THAI RUM THAT DAY.
IT WAS CHRISTMAS DAY,
ACTUALLY.
YEAH.
AND IN 2001,
IT BECAME A REALITY
ON THE OUTER BANKS.
WHAT'S BETTER--
THE BEER OR THE FOOD?
WAIT, THAT'S
A TOUGH ONE. (laughs)
TOUGH QUESTION, HUH?
I WOULDN'T PUT EITHER
ABOVE ONE OR THE OTHER.
THEY PAIR UP APPETIZERS
THAT GO WELL
WITH A CERTAIN TYPE OF BEER.
HERE YOU GO, SIR.
THE FOOD'S ALWAYS GREAT.
THERE'S ALWAYS LOCAL SPECIALS.
SALMON'S UP.
ALL CRANKED OUT
BY A SURFIN' DUDE FROM THAILAND
NAMED POK.
CHEF POK, WHAT'S YOUR REAL NAME?
WHAT'S YOUR WHOLE NAME?
PHONGKRIT CHOEICHOM.
OH, I'M GONNA
CALL YOU THAT, THEN.
CHEF POK.
ONE OF THE BEST CHEFS
ON THE OUTER BANKS.
POK DOES GREAT,
INVENTIVE STUFF.
OUR TUNA STACK'S UP.
YOU KNOW, IT'S ALWAYS
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
EVEN WHEN IT COMES
TO SOUTHERN CLASSICS.
SHRIMP AND GRITS UP.
(woman) SHRIMP AND GRITS.
I LOVE SHRIMP, I LOVE GRITS,
AND IT'S GREAT TOGETHER.
IT IS SOMETHING SPECIAL
IN POK'S SAUCE.
UH, REDEYE GRAVY.
I WAS BORN ON GRITS
AND HAM AND REDEYE GRAVY,
BUT I DON'T PUT ALL THIS
GIDDYAP IN REDEYE GRAVY.
WHAT ARE WE
STARTING WITH?
LET'S START OFF
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF OIL.
I'M GONNA ADD
OUR ONIONS.
NOW THE CELERY,
CARROTS.
SO THE MIREPOIX
GOES IN.
MIREPOIX,
A LITTLE GARLIC.
I'M GONNA ADD BAY LEAVES, THEN
FRESH THYME FROM OUR GARDEN.
COUNTRY HAM.
AND YOU'RE JUST GONNA
SWEAT THIS ALL DOWN.
SWEAT IT DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
HOW MANY HOURS
YOU WORK A WEEK?
UH, ABOUT 60, 70?
THAT'S IT?
WHAT DO YOU DO FOR
THE SECOND HALF OF THE WEEK?
GO TO THE BEACH, SURF.
DEGLAZE IT WITH COFFEE.
(whistles)
BEEF STOCK.
CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
COOK THAT DOWN HALFWAY.
TILL IT REDUCES
BY HALF.
I TASTE THE COFFEE.
NEXT UP?
NOW WE'RE GONNA
MAKE OUR GRITS.
WHOLE MILK,
CHICKEN STOCK,
ONCE THAT COMES
TO A BOIL FOR A LITTLE BIT,
WE'RE GONNA STIR IN
OUR STONE-GROUND GRITS
FROM ASHLAND, VIRGINIA.
THAT'S THE GRIT CAPITAL
OF THE WORLD, ISN'T IT?
LOOK AT THAT.
I'M GONNA ADD
OUR SALT AND PEPPER.
IT TAKES ABOUT 20, 30 MINUTES.
ONCE THAT COMES TO A THICKNESS,
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO.
LOVE IT.
WHAT'S OUR NEXT STEP?
I'M GONNA PEEL
AND DEVEIN THE SHRIMP.
THESE ARE LOCAL
NORTH CAROLINA SHRIMP.
NEVER FROZEN.
THESE ARE
THE BROWN TAIL ONES.
OKAY.
WE GOT OUR REDEYE,
IT'S ALREADY BEEN REDUCED.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IT
INTO THE CHINOIS.
THAT'S IT?
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE?
THAT'S IT.
TOSS IN A LITTLE BIT
OF OIL IN THE PAN.
PAN'S HOT,
NICE SMOKING POINT.
TOSS IN OUR SHRIMP.
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT
AND PEPPER.
I'M GONNA ADD
OUR REDEYE GRAVY.
AND THAT SHOULD BE IT.
LINE OUR GRITS UP,
LINE OUR SHRIMP,
AND DUMP OUR REDEYE GRAVY
ON TOP OF THAT.
NICE.
A LITTLE TOMATO POINT.
MICROS?
MICROGREENS,
AND, UH, OUR HOUSE-MADE
SWEET POTATO CHIPS.
VERY NICE.
ONE OF OUR
BEST-SELLING DISHES.
REALLY?
YEP.
THAT'S GOOD
REDEYE GRAVY.
THANK YOU.
REALLY NICE. SHRIMP ARE
PERFECTLY COOKED, BUDDY.
YOU USED THE BEST SHRIMP,
PUT PARMIGIANO-REGGIANO--
THE BEST
OF THE PARMESANS.
IF I LIVED IN TOWN,
YOU'D SEE ME ONCE A WEEK.
THAT'S REALLY NICE.
MMM. NICELY DONE, CHEF.
THANKS.
THE GRITS ARE MUCH CREAMIER
THAN THE GRITS I GREW UP ON.
THEY MAKE THE DISH
EXTRA SPECIAL.
GOOD FOOD, GOOD PEOPLE. THIS IS
KIND OF LIKE OUR LOCAL HANGOUT.
THIS IS RIGHTEOUS.
I MEAN, THIS IS A COOL JOINT.
WE COME IN HERE PROBABLY
TWO OR THREE TIMES A WEEK.
I LOVE THIS RESTAURANT.
(Guy) BREWING YOUR OWN BEER,
BIG, FAT KITCHEN,
CRAZY CHEF POK.
TWO DUDES SITTING ON THE BEACH
AT CHRISTMAS IN THAILAND
DRINKING CHEAP THAI RUM
END UP WITH THIS?
GIVE ME SOME
OF THAT RUM.
WEIRD THINGS HAPPEN.
COMING UP, WE'RE HEADED
TO CRANSTON, RHODE ISLAND...
YOU CAN'T COME TO RHODE ISLAND
AND NOT HAVE LITTLENECKS.
WHERE A SIDEWALK CAFé
IS MAKING UP FOR SIZE...
THE KITCHEN IS TWO-THIRDS
THE SIZE OF THE RESTAURANT.
WITH A BIG-TIME DISH.
I HAVE TO DO THIS JUST FOR
INTERNATIONAL TESTING LAWS.
THAT'S REAL.
♪♪
I LOVE ROLLING TRIPLE "D"
THROUGH THE EAST COAST,
ESPECIALLY RHODE ISLAND.
SO I'M IN THE TOWN OF CRANSTON,
ABOUT 5 MILES SOUTH
OF DOWNTOWN PROVIDENCE
IN A NEIGHBORHOOD
KNOWN AS EDGEWOOD
TO CHECK OUT THIS JOINT--
EDGEWOOD CAFE.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH.
THANK YOU.
IT'S JUST A COMFORTABLE PLACE.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE HANGING OUT
IN YOUR OWN KITCHEN.
THE FOOD IS AWESOME.
CALAMARI IN THE WINDOW.
(bell dings)
THEY'RE WILLING TO EXPERIMENT
AND TRY DIFFERENT THINGS
AND DO SPECIAL MENUS
EVERY NIGHT.
IT ENTICES YOUR TASTE BUDS.
MMM.
THAT WAS THE PLAN WHEN
OWNER AND CHEF JOHN WALSH
OPENED THIS TINY CAFé IN '08...
MEDITERRANEAN CHICKEN.
BUT HE LEFT ROOM
FOR WHAT MATTERS.
ORDER IN.
WHERE THE KITCHEN IS TWO-THIRDS
THE SIZE OF THE RESTAURANT.
IT'S MY PLAYGROUND.
SO HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE
WHAT EDGEWOOD CAFE IS LIKE?
COMFORT FOOD
WITH A GOURMET TOUCH.
WOW.
YEAH.
A COUPLE CASTANETS,
AND YOU CAN SNAP THAT OUT.
AND HE'S KEEPING THE MENU FRESH
AND SEASONAL WHENEVER POSSIBLE,
LIKE WITH THESE LOCAL CLAMS.
LITTLENECK ENTRéE.
THIS IS ALL I EVER ORDER
WHEN I COME HERE--
CLAMS WITH THIS BEAUTIFUL
SPAGHETTI,
AND, OH, THE BROTH
AND THE BREAD--FANTASTIC.
LITTLENECKS IN THE WINDOW.
PICK UP.
(bell dings)
YOU CAN'T COME TO RHODE ISLAND
AND NOT HAVE LITTLENECKS.
RIGHT.
LET'S GET HER GOING.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE
GONNA GRILL THE CORN
AND THEN THE CHORIZO.
AND WHERE'S
THE CHORIZO FROM?
LOCAL SAUSAGE
FROM NEW BEDFORD.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE
GONNA GRILL OFF THE CORN,
GRILL OFF THE SAUSAGE.
I REALLY DON'T WANT THIS
TO SOUND OUT OF LINE,
BUT I HAVE TO DO THIS JUST FOR
INTERNATIONAL TESTING LAWS.
THAT'S REAL. DELICIOUS.
A LITTLE BIT OF SPICE TO IT.
ARE WE GONNA DICE IT,
OR JUST CHOP IT UP?
CHOP IT UP.
CORN'S NICE AND ROASTED. IS IT
PEELING IT OR SHUCKING IT?
MAKE SURE I GET ALL--
PEEL THE CORN.
WHAT REALLY FREAKS ME OUT
IS THAT YOU DON'T HAVE
THIS BIG, THICK
RHODE ISLAND ACCENT.
(Rhode Island accent)
OH, THIS IS THE BEST PART.
ALL RIGHT, SO I WANT
TO CUT THIS OFF.
(normal voice) YOU WANT TO SEE
A COOL LITTLE TECHNIQUE?
YEAH.
WHEN YOU'RE DOING
A LOT OF CORN,
SEE HOW NICE THAT IS?
OH, YEAH.
NOW YOU'RE RIGHT
IN THE BOWL
AND IT'S NOT ALL OVER
THE CUTTING BOARD.
UH-HUH. VERY GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT LITTLE
TIP AND TRICK? I'M OUT.
HOW MUCH DO I OWE YOU?
NEXT UP?
MY OLIVE OIL,
LITTLENECKS.
STEAMERS.
THEN WHEN THE PAN'S HOT,
SOME GARLIC...
THAT EARLY, HUH?
SHALLOTS...
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
RED PEPPER...
THERE YOU GO.
A LITTLE SALT,
BLACK PEPPER, CILANTRO.
EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL
AT THIS POINT.
YES.
AND CHORIZO.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
WHAT'S UP WITH THAT?
AND THEN WHITE WINE,
SOME CLAM JUICE.
A LOT OF WORK
FOR ONE DISH.
OKAY, WE SEE THAT THEY'RE OPEN,
SO NOW THE CORN GOES IN.
RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT OF BUTTER,
SOME GRAPE TOMATOES.
NICE.
AND THE PASTA.
DOCTOR.
LET THAT GET HOT.
SO THE SAUSAGE, THE CLAMS,
EVERYBODY'S READY TO GO HERE?
YEP, EVERYBODY'S
READY TO GO.
GREAT.
ADD THE PASTA.
I'VE SEEN
SOME NESTING OF PASTA,
BUT NEVER
WITH A BARBECUE FORK.
WITH THE SAUSAGE SITTING
INSIDE OF THAT CLAM.
MMM. AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SERVE
THIS WITH SOME BREAD POINTS?
YEP.
OLIVE OIL WITH GARLIC AND HERBS.
GRILL THAT OFF.
RIGHT.
THIS IS HOW IT'S DONE.
GORGEOUS. LOOK AT THAT--
NICE LEAN, MEAN BROTH.
MMM. I COULD EAT THIS
ALL DAY LONG.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THE TOMATO IN THERE,
THEN YOU GET
THE SAUSAGE AND THE CLAM
AND THAT BROTH
ALL TOGETHER.
MMM, COOL.
WANT TO TRY SOME?
YES.
IT'S THE FAT OF THE SAUSAGE,
TENDERNESS OF THE CLAM,
THE FRESHNESS OF THE CORN,
THE GARLIC, THE SHALLOTS.
MMM.
EXCELLENT JOB, MAN.
NO DOUBLE-DIPPING.
LITTLENECK SPECIAL.
(man) YOU JUST WANT
TO TAKE YOUR TIME EATING IT
AND JUST ENJOY EVERY BITE.
(woman) IT'S ABSOLUTELY
JUST PERFECT.
YOU CAN'T GET THIS
ANYWHERE ELSE.
ORDER IN THE WINDOW--
FISH AND CHIPS.
THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
DIFFERENT, ALWAYS A NEW SPECIAL.
IT'S FABULOUS.
YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
(woman) I LIKE THE WAY
HE VARIES HIS DISHES.
YOU GET A LITTLE SURPRISE
EVERY TIME YOU COME IN.
A LITTLE SURPRISE?
A LITTLE SURPRISE.
COME ON DOWN AND GET
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR-TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY--
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
DON'T BE NERVOUS,
SERIOUSLY.
IT'S--LET ME TELL YOU
HOW YOU MAKE GOOD TELEVISION.
UM, IT--WELL, ACTUALLY,
MAYBE SOMEONE COULD TELL ME,
BUT, UM...
(laughs)