HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
HOLD ON TO IT,
GILLIGAN.
IT'S ALL KINDS OF COOKING...
OH, IT LOOKS LIKE FRESH SNOW
IN FLAVOR-TOWN.
DONE RIGHT...
NO.
(laughs)
OH, THAT'S WHY YOU ROCK THIS.
IN
NARRAGANSETT, RHODE ISLAND...
IF YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT
FROM SCRATCH, I'M IN.
A SUMMERTIME SHACK...
BRING IT.
COOKING UP
A SOUTH COUNTY CLASSIC...
OH! YOU COOK IT
IN BEEF FAT.
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
I DIDN'T EXPECT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
THE DOWN-LOW NEIGHBORHOOD SPOT
SMOKING UP A FEROCIOUS TAKE
ON FRENCH FRIES...
THAT'S KILLER.
AND DOING THE DANCE
WITH THE DUCK.
YOU ARE THE DEBUTANTE
OF DELICIOUS DUCK.
AND IN BOSTON, MASSACHUSETTS,
A FAMILY OWNED MEXICAN JOINT...
DOES YOUR MOM KNOW
YOU'RE USING THE BLENDER?
CONQUERING...
THEY'RE MONEY.
THE REAL DEAL CHILAQUILES...
OH, I'M COMING
TO GET THIS TOMORROW.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
♪♪
I'VE BEEN COMING TO RHODE ISLAND
FOR, LIKE, THE LAST 20 YEARS
TO VISIT THE IN-LAWS,
AND MY FATHER-IN-LAW BOB--
GREATEST GUY IN THE WORLD--
WOULD ALWAYS MAKE SURE
THAT I GOT TO TRY SOME
OF THE “REGIONAL” SPECIALTIES.
OH, HE INTRODUCED ME
TO COFFEE MILK AND HOT GRINDERS
AND HOT WIENERS AND JOHNNYCAKES.
AND THEN HE SAYS, “GUID,
YOU GOT TO TRY THIS ONE.
THIS IS A CLAM CAKE.”
I SAID, “CLAM IN A CAKE?”
SO I'M HERE IN NARRAGANSETT
RIGHT BY POINT JUDITH
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT IS ROCKING THE CLAM CAKES.
THIS IS AUNT CARRIE'S.
CLAM AND LOBSTER.
WONDERFUL FOOD,
AND IT JUST FEELS LIKE SUMMER.
GRILLED SCALLOPS.
EVERYBODY KNOWS ABOUT IT,
AND THEY DO COME BACK.
A LOT OF TIMES
IT'S YEAR AFTER YEAR.
SINCE THE '20s,
WHEN CARRIE COOPER
AND HER HUSBAND ULYSSES
OPENED THIS SUMMER-ONLY JOINT.
HEY, GIRLS.
HI, EL.
THE FAMILY TRADITION
CONTINUES TODAY
LED BY THIRD GENERATION OWNER
ELSIE FOY.
(Guy) THIS PLACE HAS GOT
TO BE BANANAS BUSY.
(Elsie) ONCE FOURTH OF JULY
ROLLS AROUND,
IT'S KIND OF BUSY EVERY--
EVERY NIGHT, YEAH.
YOU'RE DONE.
THANKS TO
THE STAR ATTRACTION...
CLAM CAKE, PLEASE.
A DEEP-FRIED
RHODE ISLAND LEGEND
THAT'S BEEN AROUND
FOR OVER 90 YEARS.
AND A GOOD CLAM CAKE
IN YOUR OPINION?
MMM.
MM-HMM.
ABSOLUTELY THE BEST.
THIS IS
THE BEST CLAM CAKE.
SO WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE FLOUR
FOR THE CLAM CAKES.
YES.
THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE MIXING IT IN?
WE ARE.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN AT HOME,
I WANT TO EXPLAIN THIS TO YOU.
THIS IS
A CEMENT MIXER.
NEVER USED FOR CEMENT.
NO, I UNDERSTAND THAT.
ALL RIGHT, SO ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
YES.
AND YOU WANT THIS
IN THE MIXER?
YES, PLEASE.
BAKING POWDER.
AND THIS IS GONNA SIT HERE
AND JUST MIX UP.
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT, TOO?
LITTLE BIT OF SALT.
(grinding)
WHAT AN AWESOME SOUND.
MIX THIS,
DUMP IT IN THE TUB.
I'M GONNA BE PUSHING THIS,
AREN'T I?
YES.
NOW IT'S CLAM CAKE TIME?
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME EGGS.
OKAY.
CLAMS.
SO THIS IS REAL DEAL.
THIS IS NOT SOME FROZEN PRODUCT.
ALL OF 'EM?
ALL OF THEM.
BUCKET O' CLAM.
WE DO ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER,
BECAUSE WE ALSO
WANT THEM FLUFFY.
OKAY.
AND OUR SPECIAL
CLAM CAKE FLOUR.
YOU WANT ME TO--
I MIGHT HAVE
TO HAVE YOU--YES.
HOLD ON TO IT, GILLIGAN. WE'VE
GOT ROUGH SEAS IN A MINUTE.
LOOK AT THAT.
PERFECT BATTER.
THE FRYER'S AT WHAT TEMP?
375.
LIKE THAT?
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT KIND OF OIL?
BEEF SHORTENING.
(record needle scratches)
NO.
(laughs)
OH, THAT'S WHY YOU ROCK THIS.
WE READY TO GO?
WE ARE READY.
SO YOU'RE JUST
GOING IN.
VERY, VERY CAREFUL.
IT TAKES ABOUT FIVE MINUTES. WE
WANT TO MAKE SURE THEY'RE DONE.
OKAY.
COMES OUT CLEAN.
LIKE A CAKE.
YOU'RE GOOD TO GO.
AND WHAT DO PEOPLE
EAT A CLAM CAKE WITH?
USUALLY WITH “CHOW-DAH”"
WITH CHOW-DAH.
YOU'RE READY TO ROCK.
WE ARE. SIMPLE, SIMPLE
SOUTH COUNTY FOOD.
OH!
YOU COOK IT IN BEEF FAT.
IT'S RICH. IT'S LIGHT.
A LOT OF CLAM FLAVOR.
MMM. THIS IS EXCEPTIONAL.
OUR BASE CHOWDER--
NOW YOU HAVE TO DIP
YOUR CLAM CAKES IN THAT.
OKAY. MM-HMM.
IT'S SIMPLY DONE--
MMM--
AND DONE TO PERFECTION.
I LOVE IT.
THANK YOU.
(woman)
COMBO WITH CLEAR CHOWDER.
YOU PULL APART THE CLAM CAKE,
DIP IT IN THE CHOWDER,
AND YOU GET TO TASTE LOTS
OF CLAMS AND A TON OF FLAVOR.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
AND ALL THAT FRESH CLAM FLAVOR
IS WHAT GOT 'EM INTO BUSINESS
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
BOWL OF PLAIN.
MY GRANDMA WAS CARRIE.
SHE AND GRANDPA CAME DOWN
TO DIG CLAMS.
SHE MADE CHOWDER
AND CLAM CAKES.
AND THE DIFFERENT FISHERMEN
WOULD SMELL THE CHOWDER
AND CLAM CAKES,
AND THEY WERE ALWAYS COMING BY
AND SAYING,
“OH, WE'D LIKE SOME OF THAT.”
SO GRANDPA PICKED UP HIS EARS.
HE SAID, “MAYBE THERE'S
SOMETHING WE CAN DO.”
BUT CLAMS WEREN'T
THE ONLY CROWD-PLEASER.
TURNS OUT AUNT CARRIE
WAS A BIT OF A BAKER, TOO...
(Elsie)
ONE PIECE OF APPLE.
SERVING UP THIS ORIGINAL
HOUSE FAVORITE.
HERE'S YOUR
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE.
THE BISCUIT IS DELICIOUS.
THE STRAWBERRIES ARE NICE
AND FRESH. I LOVE IT.
(Guy) NOW WHAT
ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME SHORTCAKE
BISCUITS FOR OUR STRAWBERRIES.
MMM.
WE ONLY SELL 'EM
WHEN THEY'RE SEASONAL HERE.
IF YOU'RE GONNA MAKE IT
FROM SCRATCH, I'M IN.
SO THE ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR.
LITTLE BIT
OF BAKING POWDER.
LITTLE BIT?
SALT.
AND WE'RE GONNA MIX THAT.
(mechanical whirring)
IT'S A CLOSE RELATIVE OF CHITTY
CHITTY BANG BANG ISN'T IT?
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THIS IS THE FUN PART.
WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR SHORTENING
IN LITTLE PIECES AT A TIME.
VERY NICE.
SO YOU CAN TURN THAT ON AGAIN
IF YOU WANT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA SLOWLY ADD
SOME COLD MILK.
OKAY.
AND YOU JUST KIND OF MIX
THAT UP. THAT'S ALL WE MIX.
JUST TO WHERE
IT'S STARTING TO HOLD TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S IT. THAT'S IT.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD NOW.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE MAKING BISCUITS.
REALLY? I THOUGHT IT ALWAYS
WORKED FROM THIS PART?
BLACK--BLACK PANTS.
DON'T START. YOU ALREADY MADE ME
DO THE HEAVY LIFTING DOWNSTAIRS.
BLACK PANTS.
YEAH. UH-HUH?
LOOK AT THAT. SO WE'RE GONNA
ROLL THIS OUT A LITTLE BIT,
A COUPLE OF INCHES HIGH.
WE ALSO HAVE OUR PAN HERE.
WE'RE GOING TO PUT
A LITTLE SPRAY ON IT.
OKAY.
WE HAVE A BISCUIT CUTTER.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
THEY'RE GONNA BE SO GOOD.
IT'S REALLY HARD TO WAIT TO GET
THE STRAWBERRIES ON 'EM,
BECAUSE THEY'RE GOOD
JUST ALONE.
JUST BY THEMSELF.
ARE WE GONNA
EGG WASH 'EM?
WE USE MILK.
JUST REGULAR,
LITTLE BIT OF MILK.
WHOLE MILK, YES.
AND HOW LONG WILL THEY GO IN
AT 500?
ABOUT 22 MINUTES,
RIGHT AROUND THERE.
(whistles) AND THEN WE BUILD
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE STRAWBERRY SAUCE.
NOW THE SAUCE.
OR HOW DO YOU SAY IT?
“SW-ACE.”
THE SAUCE WOULD BE--
NOT ME, NO. SAUCE.
YEAH, YOU SAID SW-ACE.
YOU SAID SW-ACE.
NO, I DID NOT.
NO, NO, NO.
WOULD YOU LIKE
A STRAWBERRY?
HOW ABOUT SOME SW-ACE?
THAT SHUT ME UP.
WARM WATER, SOME SUGAR--
MIX THAT TOGETHER.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA START ADDING
SOME STRAWBERRIES IN HERE.
SO I GOT
MY SIMPLE SYRUP HERE.
THE WARM WATER
IS HELPING
BREAK DOWN THE STRAWBERRY
A LITTLE BIT.
YOU ARE MASHING THEM,
SO IT IS BUILDING
A LITTLE BIT OF A...
(mouthing word)
THE BEST WOULD BE TO DO IT
THE DAY BEFORE.
YES, SO IT'D GIVE IT
A LITTLE BIT OF TIME.
NOW WE MAKE THE WHIPPED CREAM,
AND THE WHIPPED CREAM IS...
YES. HOMEMADE.
ICE-COLD MIXING BOWL,
MAKES IT MUCH FLUFFIER.
VERY CLEAN. DIG IT.
HEAVY CREAM, SUGAR,
LITTLE BIT OF VANILLA EXTRACT.
LITTLE BIT OF VANILLA.
YOU READY
FOR THE BISCUITS?
BRING IT.
ALL RIGHT.
THERE WE GO.
WOW, THAT'S DENSE. MMM.
IT'S LIKE A SCONE ALMOST.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE STRAWBERRIES.
I WONDERED WHY IT WAS IN A BOWL.
HOLY STRAWBERRIES.
HOW MUCH WHIPPED CREAM
DO YOU LIKE?
SERIOUSLY.
AND THEN,
THERE YOU GO.
SERIOUSLY, THIS IS
A NORMAL PORTION?
YES.
MMM. THE BISCUIT ITSELF
IS NOT SWEET,
AND THAT'S GOOD, BECAUSE
EVERYTHING ELSE IS SUPERSWEET.
MMM. YOU SEE THIS RIGHT HERE
WHERE I BREAK INTO IT,
AND THAT BISCUIT IS
WITHSTANDING ALL OF THE LIQUID?
YOU GET THAT REAL STRAWBERRY
FLAVOR AND THE WHIPPED CREAM.
IT'S LIKE THE PERFECT STORM
OF TEXTURES AND FLAVORS.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
YOU COMPLETELY
ROCKED THE HOUSE.
OH, THANK YOU.
(Elsie)
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE.
AND YOUR
STRAWBERRY SHORTCAKE SOUP?
IS WONDERFUL.
I'VE NEVER SEEN STRAWBERRY
SHORTCAKE LOOK LIKE THAT.
YOU NEVER HAVE?
NOT IN A BOWL.
IT'S--IT'S--OF COURSE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
HOW WE DOING OVER HERE?
DO I NEED TO COUNT CLAM CAKES?
CARRIE'S IS LIKE AN ICON
TO NARRAGANSETT,
AND IT'S JUST FUN TO SEE
THAT THE PLACE HASN'T CHANGED.
(Guy) YOU GET A CHANCE
TO COME DOWN HERE
A COUPLE TIMES
IN THE SUMMER.
THIS IS AN INDULGENCE.
YOU'RE DOWN BY THE WATER.
IF YOU'RE GONNA HAVE A CLAM
CAKE, COOK 'EM WITH LARD.
TELL MY SECRET.
OH, I AM DOWN WITH IT. I AM SO
EXCITED. YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
COMING UP...
(woman)
GET IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT,
BUT IT'S GONNA BE HOT.
WE'RE HEADED
TO ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
FOR A NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT...
SHAVED DUCK?
TAKING FRIES...
EXCELLENT.
TO A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL.
GO BIG OR GO HOME. AND AFTER
THIS, YOU'LL GO HOME BIG.
SO I'M ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM A VERY WELL-KNOWN PARK
CALLED TOWER GROVE.
NOW IN THIS OLD NEIGHBORHOOD,
THIS PLACE, WELL, USED TO BE
A GROCERY STORE,
AND IT TURNED INTO A RESTAURANT.
AND THEY SAY THAT THEY ARE
“BARBECUE, FOLK & SOUL.”
WOW. THINK THAT'S
AN INTERESTING TAG LINE?
WAIT TILL YOU GET
A LOAD OF THEIR NAME.
THIS IS THE SHAVED DUCK.
TABLE 12--WE'VE GOT DUCK BREAST,
CREAMED CORN,
MEAT LOAF
WITH MAC N CHEESE.
IT'S REALLY NICE TO SEE A REAL
RESTAURANT THAT'S GOT REAL FOOD.
WALNUT-ENCRUSTED
BACON.
AND A REAL WEIRD
SENSE OF HUMOR.
SHAVED DUCK?
MM-HMM.
YOU LIKE IT?
JUST PART OF THE CHARM
WITH SCOTTISH IMMIGRANT
ALASTAIR NISBET...
WAITING ON THE DUCK BREAST
FOR TABLE 12.
WHO OPENED THE JOINT
BACK IN '08.
EVERYTHING HAS A VERY NICE,
RICH, SMOKY FLAVOR.
THANKS TO KAT KOBYLAREK,
MASTER OF THE LINE...
DUCK BREAST,
CREAMED CORN.
AND THE PIT.
(woman)
IT TOOK US A WHILE
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT THE HECK
THEY WERE SERVING IN HERE.
I NEED YOU TO GET MY MEAT
AND BACON ON.
LET'S JUST SAY IT'S SOMETHING
ST. LOUIS FOLKS KNOW ALL ABOUT.
IT'S REAL DEAL BARBECUE.
BUT YET
KIND OF DIFFERENT.
LIKE KAT'S TAKE
ON CHEESE FRIES.
I NEVER THOUGHT THAT
YOU CAN IMPROVE ON FRENCH FRIES,
BUT THEY HAVE DONE JUST THAT.
OH, IT IS SOMETHING
I SHOULD HAVE SEEN COMING
WITH PORK BUTT AND RIB MEAT
THAT ALL STARTS
WITH A SWEET RUB.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR BROWN SUGAR,
GRANULATED SUGAR,
KOSHER SALT...
OKAY.
GRANULATED GARLIC,
HUNGARIAN PAPRIKA,
ALLSPICE.
A WHOLE BUNCH OF IT.
(coughs)
WHAT'S UP NEXT?
CORIANDER, CUMIN,
CHILI POWDER...
OKAY.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST,
OUR CLOVES.
SO YOU WORKED THIS UP.
THIS IS THE ALL-PURPOSE
SUPER RUB.
YES.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'RE GONNA RUB IT UP.
YOU'RE PRETTY JUDICIOUS
WITH THAT THERE.
YEAH, IT'S GONNA ALL
MOSTLY FALL OFF.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA DO
OUR BUTT.
(whistles)
WITH THE BONE IN?
YES, BONE-IN.
SO THESE ARE RUBBED,
READY TO GO.
YES.
LET 'EM SIT UP FOR ABOUT
15 MINUTES. WE'LL TAKE 'EM OUT.
THREE-QUARTERS OF THE HICKORY
AND...
25% WHITE OAK.
I'LL GET THIS.
YOU GRAB YOUR RACK.
I GOT MY RACK.
AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT.
SWAP ME.
ALL RIGHT, HOW LONG
ARE WE GONNA LET THIS GO?
RIBS ARE GONNA SMOKE
FOR ABOUT FIVE HOURS.
THE BUTT'S GONNA SMOKE
FOR, UH, ABOUT 16.
OUR BEAUTIFUL BUTTS
HAVE BEEN OFF THE SMOKER.
WE'RE GONNA PULL IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. NICE SMOKE.
SO WE SHRED THE BUTT.
ARE WE GONNA PULL
THE MEAT OFF THIS, TOO?
YES, WE ARE.
OH, NICE JOB.
IS IT--
GOOD LUCK.
YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
THANKS.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'VE GOT
ENOUGH PORK.
WE'RE GONNA GET OUR RIBS THAT
YOU'VE ALREADY GOTTEN MESSY.
I LIKE THAT RUB.
THANK YOU.
IS THAT ENOUGH
FOR THE SMOTHERED?
LET ME PULL
THIS LAST LITTLE BIT.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S DO THIS.
LET'S MAKE THE CHEESE SAUCE.
GREAT.
SO WE'RE GONNA START
WITH OUR HEAVY CREAM.
AND THEN WE'VE GOT
OUR 2% MILK.
WE'RE GONNA PUT
OUR CHEESE IN THERE.
WHAT TYPE OF CHEESE?
AMERICAN,
WHITE AMERICAN.
SO WE'VE GOT
A LITTLE ROUX STARTED.
YEP. IT'S GONNA THICKEN
OUR SAUCE.
ADD A LITTLE BIT
AT A TIME.
THAT'S OUR CHEESE SAUCE
THAT'S GONNA GO OVER TOP
OF THE SMOTHERED.
RIGHT.
AND WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE MEAT TO IT.
IT'S GONNA ALL BE INCORPORATED.
WE'RE NOT LAYERING IT.
AND WHAT ARE WE GONNA
SERVE THIS OVER?
CRISPY FRIES,
HAND-CUT. HAND-CUT.
HAND-CUT.
ALL RIGHT.
MUNCHKIN AMOUNT
OF SALT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA DO A LITTLE
BIT OF WHITE CHEDDAR CHEESE
AND SOME SCALLIONS.
NICE.
VOILà.
YOU KNOW, WHEN I WALKED INTO
THIS PLACE, I SMELLED THE SMOKE,
SO I KNEW THAT IT HAD
A LITTLE BIT OF FUNK,
BUT I DIDN'T EXPECT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MMM. THAT'S KILLER.
IT'S NOT
SUPERHEAVY CHEESE.
IT'S A CHEESE SAUCE,
WHICH I LIKE.
MMM. I MEAN, I'M TELLING YOU,
THE FRIES ARE CRISPY.
MMM.
SEE, WHAT I LIKE IS
THAT YOU TAKE SOMETHING
THAT IS A GUILTY INDULGENCE,
AND YOU DO IT THE RIGHT WAY.
SO IF YOU'RE GONNA DO IT,
GO BIG OR GO HOME.
(Kat)
SMOTHERED FRIES.
THANKS FOR THE FRIES.
FRIES GALORE.
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING
GOING FOR IT,
AND DECADENT IS THE WORD
FOR THIS.
YOU COME TO THIS PLACE
TO KIND OF BE HERE AND HANG OUT.
IF THE FOOD WASN'T GOOD, PEOPLE
WOULDN'T COME BACK IN DROVES.
(Guy) TOWER GROVE EAST
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
HANGING OUT AT SHAVED DUCK,
AND WHEN YOU COME BACK,
WE ARE GONNA MAKE SOME DUCK,
FINALLY.
GET THE DUCK OUT OF HERE.
(laughs)
OKAY. OH, OH.
WELCOME BACK. WE'RE HANGING OUT
AT THE SHAVED...
DUCK.
IN...
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
EXCELLENT.
AND IF YOU'RE A LOCAL,
YOU JUST CALL IT THE DUCK.
IT'S IN THE MIDDLE
OF A NEIGHBORHOOD.
WE'RE IN A GREAT SPOT
IN ST. LOUIS.
AND WE'RE OFF THE BEATEN PATH,
WHICH IS FUN.
THE BEGINNING WAS
A LITTLE BIT DIFFICULT,
BECAUSE WE WERE
SO HARD TO FIND.
UNLESS YOU FOLLOWED YOUR NOSE.
THEY'VE GOT A BIG OLD SMOKER
IN THE BACKYARD.
SO GOOD.
(Guy) WE'VE MADE
SMOTHERED FRIES
WITH THE PULLED MEAT FROM
THE PORK BUTT AND FROM THE RIBS.
NOW FINALLY
WE'RE GONNA DO DUCK.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THIS
HAVE A STEAM BATH,
SO WE'RE GONNA POUR
SOME WATER IN OUR PAN.
WHY ARE YOU STANDING
ON ONE FOOT?
ARE YOU JUST...
I'M A FLAMINGO.
SEE THE PINK?
ALL RIGHT, SO THEN WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE PERFORATED PAN
ON TOP OF THAT.
SO NOW WE'RE TAKING IT
TO THE SMOKER.
HOW LONG ARE
WE GONNA LET THIS GO?
3 TO 4 HOURS AT 220.
THIS IS THE SAUCE
THAT'S GONNA GO ON TOP.
IT'S CHERRY JUNIPER JAM.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
FIRST WE NEED TO MAKE
THE GARNI BOUQUET--
BAY LEAVES, JUNIPER BERRIES,
AND MIXED PEPPERCORNS.
OKAY.
SO WE'RE GONNA TIE
THIS LITTLE LOVE POUCH.
A LITTLE BIT OF WHITE WINE,
WATER,
RED WINE VINEGAR,
SUGAR.
AND SOME CHERRIES.
THESE ARE GOOD.
GET IN THERE.
ALL RIGHT,
BUT IT'S GONNA BE HOT.
(laughs)
ALL RIGHT,
LITTLE GARNI IN THERE.
AND WE'RE GONNA LET THIS COOK
DOWN FOR ABOUT 10, 15 MINUTES.
KIND OF JUST LET IT MARINATE.
LET THE MAGIC HAPPEN.
ALL RIGHT, ON THE FLATTOP.
WE'RE GONNA RENDER IT DOWN.
(humming)
OOH, THAT LOOKS NICE.
SO I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND CUT IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S HOT. OOH.
THIS IS AN ORDER?
YEAH.
(whistles)
ALL RIGHT.
GORGEOUS.
A LA SHAVE A LA DUCK.
GET THE DUCK OUT OF HERE.
(laughs)
OH, OH.
THAT'S RIGHTEOUS DUCK.
IT'S NOT OVERSMOKED.
THERE'S NOT TOO MUCH SMOKE.
YOU STILL GET THE DUCK FLAVOR.
SUPER TENDER.
FAT RENDERED DOWN.
CRISPY SKIN.
AND THE CHERRY JUNIPER JAM--
IT'S RICH, BUT IT'S LIGHT.
AND IF YOU DON'T THINK YOU LIKE
DUCK, THIS--THIS IS DUCK TO TRY.
YOU ARE THE DEBUTANTE
OF DELICIOUS DUCK.
SMOKED DUCK BREAST.
OOH.
THE DUCK ITSELF
IS VERY TENDER.
IT JUST REALLY MELTS
IN YOUR MOUTH.
IT IS AN AMAZING GEM.
IT REALLY IS.
(Alistair) EVERYONE THAT WORKS
FOR THE RESTAURANT...
NAILS IT.
THEY'VE MADE IT THE RESTAURANT
THAT IT IS. THEY REALLY HAVE.
(Kat) HERE'S
THOSE CHEESE FRIES.
IF YOU WERE TO SAY
TO SOMEBODY THAT
“I'M GOING TO THE SHAVED DUCK,”
PEOPLE LOOK AT YOU CROSS-EYED?
IT'S GOOD TO HAVE A PLACE LIKE
THIS RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
SO WE'LL JUST KEEP IT
A SECRET.
YEAH.
UP NEXT...
(bell dings)
WE'RE CRUISING
TO EAST BOSTON...
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THE BRUCE LEE COOKING TECHNIQUE.
FOR AN AUTHENTIC TASTE
OF, YOU GUESSED IT,
PUEBLA, MEXICO.
CHILAQUILES.
OH, I LOVE IT.
THIS IS A BODY BY CHILAQUILES.
SO HERE I AM
ON THE EAST SIDE OF BOSTON,
ONE OF MY FAVORITE PLACES.
NOW LAST COUPLE TIMES
I WAS HERE, IT WAS ALL ITALIAN.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT RINO'S
AND ITALIAN EXPRESS PIZZERIA.
BUT LIKE I SAID,
THIS IS LIKE A VIRTUAL
CORNUCOPIA OF ETHNIC FOOD.
WHAT AM I FEELING LIKE TODAY?
YOU KNOW IT--MEXICAN,
HERE AT ANGELA'S CAFé.
RAJAS POBLANAS.
IT'S THE BEST MEXICAN
IN THE CITY, HANDS DOWN.
(woman) HERE'S A PEPIAN ROJO
WITH CACTUS.
EVERYTHING--
IT HAS SO MUCH FLAVOR.
(woman) HERE'S
YOUR MOLE POBLANO.
THIS IS WHAT
REAL MEXICAN FOOD IS.
JUST LIKE THEY DO IT
IN PUEBLA, MEXICO,
THE HOMETOWN
OF THE GARCIA FAMILY.
WE HAVE THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS
IN OUR BLOOD.
IN YOUR BLOOD.
(man) PICK UP, GUYS.
MOLE POBLANO CON POLLO.
SO, OF COURSE, WHEN LUIS
CAME TO THE STATES IN '92,
HE STARTED COOKING RIGHT AWAY.
A FEW YEARS LATER,
HE ASKED HIS MOM ANGELA
TO JOIN HIM IN BEAN TOWN.
SHE'S IN THE KITCHEN,
MOSTLY IN THE, YOU KNOW...
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
YOU MAKE YOUR MOM
DO THE COOKING?
MY MOM'S BEEN IN THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS FOR, LIKE, 50 YEARS.
SO SHE'S TAUGHT LUIS
TO MAKE ALL OF HIS FAVORITE
CHILDHOOD MEALS THE RIGHT WAY.
MY MOTHER DOESN'T BELIEVE
IN CANNED STUFF.
IT HAS TO BE
FROM SCRATCH.
DOWN TO THE HOMEMADE
TOMATILLO SAUCE
ON ONE OF MY ALL-TIME
MEXICAN FAVORITES.
(Luis) CHILAQUILES VERDES
CON POLLO.
THIS IS JUST AMAZING.
CHILAQUILES.
OH, I LOVE IT.
HAVE YOU
TRIED THEM BEFORE?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THIS IS?
(laughs)
THIS IS A BODY
BY CHILAQUILES.
ALL RIGHT,
GOOD, GOOD, GOOD.
COME ON, MAN.
WHAT ARE
WE GONNA MAKE?
THE TOMATILLO SAUCE.
SO THE TOMATILLOS
USUALLY HAVE
A NICE PAPER SKIN
ON THE OUTSIDE OF 'EM.
EXACTLY.
SOME JALAPEÑO.
JALAPEÑO.
WE'RE GONNA BOIL THE JALAPEÑOS
AND THE TOMATILLOS?
EXACTLY. TOGETHER.
GOT IT.
WE TAKE THE TOMATILLOS
AND THE JALAPEÑOS
OUT OF THE HOT WATER.
OKAY.
WOW.
THERE YOU GO.
SO NOW WE ADD
A LITTLE WATER...
OKAY.
SALT.
JUST BETWEEN YOU AND ME,
DOES YOUR MOM KNOW
YOU'RE USING THE BLENDER?
SHE ALLOWS ME
TO DO THAT.
SHH. DON'T DRAG ME
INTO THIS.
GARLIC.
AND THEN WE'RE JUST READY
TO BLEND IT.
SO NOW WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS OBVIOUSLY COOK THE SAUCE.
SO WE ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OLIVE OIL.
WE HAVE TO STRAIN THE SAUCE.
AND YOU'VE GOT TO GO
LIKE THIS.
OH, OH.
THIS IS
PART OF THE SHOW.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
THE BRUCE LEE COOKING TECHNIQUE.
EXACTLY.
WE ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE ADD
JUST A LITTLE SALT.
OKAY.
WE HAVE TO ADD
THE EPAZOTE.
I KNOW EPAZOTE. YOU CAN'T
FIND THAT VERY OFTEN.
YOU'RE JUST GONNA LET THAT
STEEP IN THERE...
EXACTLY.
BUILD THE FLAVOR.
NEXT STEP?
WE'RE GONNA FRY
THE TORTILLAS.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE JUST PUT
A LITTLE SAUCE IN HERE,
A LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY.
WHICH YOU MAKE YOURSELF.
OF COURSE YOU DO.
EXACTLY.
EVERYTHING IS HOMEMADE.
OTHERWISE ANGELA GETS UPSET.
SO WE JUST LET IT SIT LIKE THAT
FOR TWO MINUTES.
OKAY.
AND THEN WE PUT
THE TORTILLA CHIPS.
YEP.
THEY'RE STILL GONNA HAVE
A LITTLE BIT OF CRUNCH TO 'EM,
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF TEXTURE.
SOAK UP THAT SAUCE
RIGHT NOW.
SO IN THE MEANTIME, WE'RE GONNA
START COOKING THE EGGS.
OH!
DO YOU LIKE EGGS?
HOW DO YOU WANT THEM?
NO, BUT I'LL BE BACK.
WHATEVER YOU DO,
DO NOT LET THEM BE RUNNY.
ALL RIGHTY.
MMM.
SO OVER-HARD, RIGHT?
OVER THERE
WOULD BE BETTER.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD.
LET'S HAVE
SOME CHILAQUILES.
THAT--
LET'S CHILA-HURRY UP-A.
YOU'RE CHILA-KILLING ME.
WE'RE GONNA GARNISH IT
WITH SOUR CREAM...
YEP.
SHREDDED CHICKEN,
AND SOME FRESH CHEESE.
QUESO FRESCO.
A LITTLE ONIONS.
AVOCADO. REFRITO.
AND THE EGGS.
THERE YOU GO, ON THE SIDE.
GOOD MAN!
A LITTLE PARSLEY.
IT'S READY TO SERVE.
OKAY.
ENJOY.
OH, MAN.
THAT IS AWESOME.
MMM!
AND YOU GET SOME OF THAT
JALAPEÑO BITE RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
BUT THEN YOU GET
THIS TEXTURE.
THE TORTILLA'S A LITTLE BIT SOFT
BUT STILL HAS SOME CRUNCH.
AND THEN YOU GET A LITTLE
OF THE ACID FROM THE TOMATILLO.
A LITTLE FRESH ONION.
THE BITE, THE HEAT,
THE CRUNCH, THE CREAM,
THE CHICKEN, THE MONEY.
OH, I'M COMING
TO GET THIS TOMORROW. WOW.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
THE FLAVORS ARE UNBELIEVABLE.
(woman) YOU REALLY CAN'T GET
ANYTHING LIKE THIS AROUND HERE.
IT'S INCREDIBLY SATISFYING
FROM TOP TO BOTTOM.
IT'S THIS GREAT LITTLE SPOT
THAT YOU CAN COME HERE
THREE TIMES A DAY
AND GET THESE GREAT MEALS.
YOU COME HERE. YOU EAT HERE.
YOU LEAVE.
AND YOU FEEL GOOD AND HAPPY.
BREAKFAST, LUNCH, AND DINNER,
I CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF ANGELA'S.
AWESOME. FANTASTIC.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
IF YOU WANT TO CHECK OUT
SOME OF THE RECIPES
FOR THE JOINTS WE VISIT,
GO TO foodnetwork.com.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
“DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.”
LUKE, I AM YOUR FATHER.
COME TO THE DARK SIDE.
(laughs)
THAT'S ALL, FOLKS.