I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP,
IT'S VOLUME UP TO 11...
OOH!
A LITTLE SPICY.
(speaking indistinctly)
FOR AN OFF-THE-HOOK MEDLEY
OF FOOD MASH-UP...
YEAH!
IN
SOMERVILLE, MASSACHUSETTS...
"CHEDDAH."
WICKED CHEDDAH.
WE'LL WORK ON THAT.
THE BURGER JOINT...
COME HERE,
AND GO HOME BIG.
DOING A RIGHTEOUS COVER...
MAC ATTACK.
OF A CLASSIC CHEESEBURGER.
I'VE SEEN RIDICULOUS
IN THE BURGER WORLD.
THIS MIGHT HAVE TO BE
A CONTENDER.
IN MIDDLETOWN, RHODE ISLAND...
TRYING TO BREAK LOOSE.
A FISH STORE/RESTAURANT...
I'M DYIN' OVER HERE.
SPINNING SOMETHING
CALLED A STUFFIE...
A BIG CLAM, AND IT'S
GOT BIG CLAM FLAVOR.
AND DOING THE ASIAN TOUR
ON CALAMARI.
GO CRAZY ON THIS.
AND IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
HUH?
THE FILIPINO FOOD TRUCK...
OH, THESE DUDES
ARE ROCKIN' IT.
CRANKING OUT
ROCK STAR DISHES...
HOLY MOLY.
AND NUMBER ONE HITS...
BANANAS.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
YOU KNOW, I THINK ONE
OF THE BIG MISUNDERSTANDINGS
ABOUT
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES"
IS THAT I EAT AT BURGER JOINTS,
LIKE, ALL THE TIME,
WHICH IS NOT REALLY THE CASE.
SO WHEN I DO EAT
AT A BURGER JOINT,
IT'S GOTTA BE A PLACE THAT'S,
YOU KNOW, OUTSIDE THE BOX,
SO HERE I AM OUTSIDE OF BOSTON
IN SOMERVILLE, MASS.,
TO CHECK OUT
THE BOSTON BURGER COMPANY.
WE GOT ANOTHER KILLER BEE.
IT'S A GREAT
REPRESENTATION OF BOSTON.
GREEN MONSTER'S UP.
HE HAS THE BEST BURGERS
IN TOWN.
I WOULDN'T EAT A BURGER
ANYWHERE ELSE IN BOSTON.
(woman) HOMEMADE, FRESH.
YOU DON'T FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
EATING SOMETHING OUT OF A BOX.
HANDMADE AND GRILLED UP DAILY
BY OWNER PAUL MALVONE...
TABLE TWO, HOT MESS.
WHO MAILED IN A JOB
AT THE POST OFFICE
TO GET BACK
TO HIS RESTAURANT ROOTS.
I WAS COOKING FOR A LITTLE
WHILE, AND I LIKED IT,
AND THEN I GOT OUT OF IT
AND GOT INTO THE POSTAL SERVICE.
I MISSED IT, SO I DECIDED
TO COME BACK TO IT.
ORDERS UP.
AND HE CAME BACK
IN A BIG WAY,
CREATING 28 DIFFERENT KINDS
OF GOURMET BURGERS.
WE'VE GOT THE KILLER BEE
FIRST.
IT'S SO GOOD. IT'S GOT,
LIKE, BACON AND ONION RINGS
AND CHEESE AND THIS SWEET,
DELECTABLE BARBECUE SAUCE.
SO GOOD.
GOT THE PILGRIM BURGER.
TURKEY BURGER, STUFFING,
CRANBERRY MAYO.
IT'S BASICALLY THANKSGIVING
DINNER IN YOUR MOUTH.
BUT HE'S GOT
THIS ONE BURGER...
THE MAC ATTACK.
THAT'S THE DICTIONARY
DEFINITION OF COMFORT FOOD.
MAC AND CHEESE AND A BURGER--
TWO BEST THINGS.
YOU'D TOTALLY RECOMMEND IT TO
ANYBODY THAT'S A BURGER FAN.
HIGHLY RECOMMEND.
IT'S WICKED AWESOME.
I'M GONNA MAKE
SOME MAC AND CHEESE.
I'M GONNA MAKE THE CHEESE SAUCE.
TAKE CHOPPED ONIONS, THE BUTTER,
WE'RE GONNA LET THAT
SWEAT UP.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA
THROW THE FLOUR RIGHT IN.
OKAY, SO WE'VE GOT
THE ROUX BUILT,
COOKED OUT THE FLOUR,
GOT THE ONIONS IN THERE,
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA GO
WITH SOME MILK.
WE'RE GONNA GO WITH SOME MILK.
CHEESES--
AMERICAN,
GONNA THROW SOME CHEDDAR.
CHEDDAH.
WICKED CHEDDAH.
NO, WE DEFINITELY
GET THE ACCENT GOING.
WE'LL WORK ON THAT.
THEN WE'RE GONNA THROW IN SOME
SHREDDED CHEDDAR JACK CHEESE.
THAT COMES WITH A FREE
SUBSCRIPTION TO LIPITOR,
OR WHAT?
IT'S CHEESE.
AND LISTEN...
IT'S MILK.
YOU NEED DAIRY.
SO STIR IT UP, GET IT DONE,
BOIL SOME WATER,
MAKE SOME PASTA,
AND THERE WE GO.
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL RIGHT,
CHEESE SAUCE IS MADE.
GONNA THROW
A LITTLE HOT SAUCE.
WHO'S HOT SAUCE?
THIS IS
FRANK'S HOT SAUCE.
WE'RE GONNA MIX THIS UP.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S A GOOD-LOOKIN' MAC.
NEW INGREDIENT
I'M ADDING
TO MY MAC AND CHEESE
FLAVOR PROFILE IS HOT SAUCE.
OH, WHERE'S THAT BEEN
ALL MY LIFE?
áNDELE.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA
THROW SOME PARMESAN,
A LITTLE PECORINO ROMANO.
HOW YOU DOIN'
WITH THAT RIGHT THERE?
AND WE'RE GONNA THROW IN
SOME SALT AND PEPPER.
(whistles)
WE'RE JUST GONNA
MIX THIS RIGHT UP.
IT'S LIKE A WORKOUT.
(as Arnold Schwarzenegger)
YOU A CHAMPION.
YOU CAN DO IT, MAN.
WORK OUT HARDER.
(normal voice)
NOW YOU DUMP IT IN THE PAN,
LET IT SET UP OVERNIGHT.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND WHY ARE WE
LETTING IT SET UP?
IF IT'S TOO HOT,
IT'S GONNA FALL APART.
TOO HOT,
IT'LL FALL A-POT?
FALL APART WHEN
IT GETS ON THE GRILL.
WE'RE GONNA GRILL
THE MAC AND CHEESE?
YEP.
OKAY.
GONNA THROW A BURGER
RIGHT DOWN.
OKAY. NICE 80-20.
NEVER FROZEN?
NEVER FROZEN. WE MAKE EVERY ONE
OF THESE BY HAND EVERY DAY.
WE'LL THROW ON
SOME BACON.
THE BACON'S COOKED
TO ORDER EACH TIME?
YES, SIR.
THIS WAY, IT COMES OUT NICE.
IT'S GONNA BE NICE AND PLIABLE.
BUNS ON. WE TOAST
ALL OUR BUNS.
AND THE BUNS ARE LOCAL?
THE BUNS ARE LOCAL.
THROW THAT RIGHT ON THE GRILL.
PUT SOME CHEDDAR JACK
CHEESE ON.
I'M GONNA GET, LIKE,
ONE OF THOSE ROAD CONSTRUCTION
SIGNS ON MY HEART.
LOOK AT THIS.
I'VE SEEN RIDICULOUS
IN THE BURGER WORLD.
THIS MIGHT HAVE TO BE
A CONTENDER.
MAC ATTACK.
LOOK AT THAT GOODNESS
FROM THE FLATTOP.
MMM. I'M TELLING YOU WHAT,
PRETTY ROCKIN'
MAC AND CHEESE, BRO.
MMM.
REALLY GOOD MEAT
IN THE BURGER.
IT'S GOT GOOD TOOTH TO IT, GOOD
CHEW, GOOD TEXTURE, GOOD FAT.
THE BUN DOES A GREAT PART
WHERE IT JUST KIND OF ABSORBS
INTO ALL THESE FLAVORS.
IF YOU'RE GONNA GO
FOR A BIG BURGER,
PUTTING MAC AND CHEESE ON IT
IS PRETTY GANGSTER.
GO BIG OR GO HOME.
OR COME HERE
AND GO HOME BIG.
TABLE FOUR, MAC ATTACK.
ALL RIGHT,
HOPE WE'RE HUNGRY.
I'VE HAD A LOT
OF MAC AND CHEESE,
BUT, UH, THIS TAKES
THE PRIZE,
BEST I'VE EVER HAD.
IT JUST GETS GOOEY AND CHEESY
AND STRINGY AND...
(Guy) THERE IS JUST SOMETHING
ABOUT CUTE GIRLS
EATING BIG BURGERS,
HUH?
I'M GONNA MAKE
A CALENDAR.
WATCH THE BURGERS.
(Guy) YOU MAKE THE CHIPS.
YOU MAKE THE SLAW.
YOU MAKE YOUR SAUCES.
YOU DO ALL YOUR MAYOS.
YOU'RE PRETTY MUCH
A SCRATCH-MADE BURGER JOINT.
PRETTY MUCH.
TRY HARD.
I'M IMPRESSED.
GIVE ME A HUG.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THERE YOU GO. SEE?
NOW HE'S IN IT TO WIN IT.
UP NEXT, A ROAD TRIP
TO MIDDLETOWN, RHODE ISLAND...
WAY TO LIVE
ON THE EDGE.
FOR THE TRICKS
ON COOKING UP A QUAHOG...
GOOD WITH
A COLD ONE.
DUDE, IT'D GO GOOD
WITH A COLD THREE.
AND PUTTING
AN ASIAN SPIN ON SQUID.
GETTING DOWN WITH THE PEANUTS.
PEANUTS ARE IN HERE.
I'VE BEEN TO
NEWPORT, RHODE ISLAND,
A BUNCH OF TIMES,
BUT TO BE HONEST,
I'VE NEVER VISITED THE OTHER TWO
TOWNS HERE ON AQUIDNECK ISLAND--
THAT'S PORTSMOUTH,
AND THIS IS MIDDLETOWN.
I MEAN, I WANT TO GO
WHERE THE LOCALS LIVE,
WHERE THE LOCALS HANG OUT,
WHERE THE LOCALS EAT,
LIKE THIS JOINT--
FISH MARKET AND RESTAURANT,
THIS IS ANTHONY'S SEAFOOD.
ONE LOBSTER DINNER
COMING UP.
KUNG PAO CALAMARI.
THE FOOD IS ALWAYS GOOD.
I JUST DON'T THINK YOU
COULD GET BETTER SEAFOOD.
(Guy) FULL-BLOWN
WHOLESALE SEAFOOD SHOP,
RETAIL SEAFOOD SHOP,
AND A RESTAURANT.
RIGHT.
NICE FAMILY BUSINESS.
THAT GOES ALL THE WAY BACK
TO 1956,
WHEN ANTHONY BUCOLO
STARTED SELLING LOBSTERS.
NOW SONS MICHAEL AND STEVE
AND GRANDSON LOGAN
ARE ALL IN THE GAME.
THEY'RE, LIKE,
THE BEST GUYS ON EARTH.
SO IT'S THE FOUR
MUSKETEERS.
ON THE FRESH SIDE.
CAN I HELP YOU WITH ANYTHING?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'D LIKE?
SOME SALMON.
YOU'RE THE COOK SIDE.
STANDARD
NEW ENGLAND RECIPES.
ONE LOBSTER ROLL.
ORDER UP
ON THE CLAM CAKES.
THE FRIED CLAM STRIPS
ARE MY FAVORITE.
AND A LOCAL DISH THE BUCOLO
FAMILY GREW UP WITH.
STUFFIES, GOING IN.
CLAMS, PEPPERS,
AND THEN THERE'S
CHOURICO IN IT
INSIDE A CLAM SHELL.
QUAHOG, LOCAL,
OUT OF NARRAGANSETT BAY,
TO THE EAST OF US.
THAT'S A HONKER.
LET'S GET STARTED.
IN A MEDIUM-SIZE PAN,
WE'RE GONNA PUT OUR QUAHOG.
AND WE'RE GONNA PUT...
EAR PLUGS.
4 OUNCES OF WATER.
LET'S JUST STEAM 'EM.
AS SOON AS THEY
POP OPEN.
THIS IS GONNA GO
UNTIL THEY OPEN,
PROBABLY ABOUT
FIVE MINUTES.
AND IT'S
THE SAME PRINCIPLE,
IF THEY DON'T OPEN,
YOU DON'T USE IT.
CORRECT.
THE JUICE WE'RE
GONNA STRAIN.
JUICE WE'RE
GONNA STRAIN,
JUST TO MAKE SURE
ANY SAND GETS CAUGHT.
AND THAT SHOULD BE
JUST ENOUGH WATER.
WOW.
GONNA BROWN
EVERYTHING ELSE UP.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE BUTTER,
RED AND GREEN, UM,
CHERRY PEPPER,
WHITE ONION,
AND ALREADY GROUND CHOURICO--
SMOKED PORTUGUESE SAUSAGE.
JUST GONNA STIR THIS UP.
OKAY, SO WHILE
WE'RE COOKING THAT DOWN,
WE DO THE CLAMS?
ANYBODY WANT TO
CHUG THE CLAM WATER?
WE'RE GONNA RECONSTITUTE
THOSE CROUTONS.
THIS IS GONNA
MAKE THEM TENDER.
THIS IS ALSO GONNA BECOME
A SERVING PLATE.
JUST GONNA PUT 'EM
RIGHT BACK IN THIS SHELL.
REALLY WANT TO KEEP--
SO YOU WANT TO DO IT
SO YOU HAVE SOME TEXTURE.
CORRECT.
NOT TRYING TO MAKE
PASTE.
AND WE'RE ALL
BROWNED OFF THERE.
OKAY, WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE CHOPPED QUAHOG.
BROWN THAT OFF.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
A LITTLE FRESH PARSLEY.
SMELLS GOOD.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE STRAINED CLAM BROTH
TO THE CROUTONS
TO RECONSTITUTE THEM.
AWESOME.
ADD A LITTLE BREAD CRUMB,
JUST SO IT'S NOT TOO WET.
AND WE'LL JUST
INCORPORATE IT REAL GOOD.
ENOUGH ALREADY.
CAN WE PUT IT IN THE SHELLS?
I'M DYING OVER HERE.
HOW MANY OUNCES?
ABOUT 5.5 OUNCES.
IN THE OVEN, 350.
ALL RIGHT.
GOT A NICE CRUST
ON 'EM.
SERVE 'EM, ONE UP.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THE FLAVOR'S SO RICH
IN THE CHOURICO
AND IN THE QUAHOG ITSELF.
HIT IT WITH
SOME HOT SAUCE THERE.
OH.
A BIG CLAM, AND IT'S
GOT BIG CLAM FLAVOR.
GO GOOD WITH
A COLD ONE.
DUDE, IT'D GO GOOD
WITH A COLD THREE.
MONEY. GREAT RECIPE.
THE STUFFIE
IS VERY FRESH.
HAS A KICK TO 'EM.
(girl) IT JUST HAS A LITTLE BIT
OF SPICE FROM THE CHOURICO
BUT IT'S STILL
VERY GOOD.
I LOVE THE FACT THAT
THERE'S RETAIL OUT FRONT,
AND THEN YOU CAN COME
IN HERE AND GET THE SAME
HIGH QUALITY SEAFOOD--
GREAT FISH AND CHIPS,
OR SOMETHING AS EXTREME
AS THE KUNG PAO CALAMARI.
KUNG PAO CALAMARI.
NEVER SEEN IT BEFORE
IN ANOTHER RESTAURANT.
A LITTLE DIFFERENT SPIN
ON THE CALAMARI.
I'M A BIG KUNG PAO FAN.
WHAT ARE WE STARTING WITH?
ALL RIGHT.
WE ARE MAKING KUNG PAO SAUCE.
WE'RE STARTING
WITH OUR PLUM SAUCE.
OKAY.
HERE WE HAVE
OUR GARLIC CHILI PASTE.
SAMBAL.
YEAH. SESAME OIL,
RICE WINE VINEGAR,
WHITE SESAME SEED, BLACK SESAME
SEED, AND FRESH CILANTRO,
AND THEN I JUST WHIP
THAT UP A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE WATER IN
JUST TO THIN IT OUT
A LITTLE BIT.
ALL OF IT?
ALL OF IT.
WAY TO LIVE
ON THE EDGE.
THAT PASSES.
WHAT DO WE DREDGE IT IN?
WE'RE GONNA
MAKE THAT NEXT.
LET'S GO.
HERE WE HAVE A FINE
GROUND YELLOW FLOUR.
WE'LL OFFSET IT WITH A LITTLE
COARSER GROUND YELLOW FLOUR
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF BAKING POWDER.
INCORPORATE ALL THAT
TOGETHER.
THIS IS GONNA GO
TO OUR BREADING STATION.
OKAY.
CALAMARI.
YOU'RE GONNA SIT THERE
AND TOSS IT RIGHT IN THERE.
IF THEY LOSE ONE,
THERE'S GONNA BE AN ISSUE.
NO, WE TRY NOT TO LOSE TOO MANY.
WE'RE DIGGING AROUND.
WE'LL FIND 'EM.
WE GOT IT.
WE'RE USING
ZERO TRANS FAT SOY.
VERY NICE, EXCELLENT.
LAST MINUTE, YOU THROW
SOME HOT PEPPERS IN THERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A LOT OF CALAMARI.
DOUBLE ORDER.
WHILE WE'RE HERE,
I'M GONNA ADD SOME PEANUTS
FOR A LITTLE SALTINESS.
OUR KUNG PAO SAUCE--
WE'LL JUST PUT IT IN HERE.
AND JUST A LITTLE
SCALLION.
BEAUTIFUL PLATE.
THOSE ITALIAN PEPPERS.
MMM.
CALAMARI IS SO TENDER.
YOU DIDN'T KILL IT
WITH THE SAUCE--
IT'S NOT JUST COVERED IN IT,
SALTY OF THE PEANUTS,
ALL THAT TIED TOGETHER--
DYNAMITE.
REALLY GOOD. THANK YOU.
MMM. GO CRAZY ON THIS.
THE CALAMARI IS AWESOME.
IT'S FRESH.
IT'S NOT RUBBERY AT ALL.
PEANUTS IN IT.
GETTING DOWN
WITH THE PEANUTS.
PEANUTS ARE IN HERE.
I GET THIS.
YOU CAN ALWAYS COUNT ON IT
BEING AS FRESH AS CAN BE.
(woman) THIS IS WHAT
THEY'RE ALL ABOUT HERE.
SHE'S IN THE RESTAURANT
BUSINESS,
AND SHE BUYS
FROM THESE FOLKS,
AND YOU COME EAT
AT THEIR RESTAURANT.
WE GET TO GO--
THEN WHAT ELSE DO YOU GUYS
WANT FROM ME? ALL RIGHT.
I MEAN, THAT'S ABOUT AS LEGIT
AS AN OFFERING AS YOU CAN GET.
COMIN' UP...
OH, OH!
WE'RE ROLLING INTO
ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
EASILY, I APPROACH.
FOR A SPOT
ON A NINJA FOOD TRUCK...
THIS FOOD, DAWG,
IT AIN'T NO JOKE.
ROCKIN' OUT
A FILIPINO FOOD FEST.
MM-HMM.
(mumbling)
♪♪
YOU KNOW, NO MATTER WHERE YOU GO
IN THE UNITED STATES TODAY,
YOU CAN FIND FOOD TRUCKS
OF EVERY SHAPE,
EVERY SIZE,
AND EVERY ETHNICITY.
SO I'M HERE
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
ON THE CORNER OF, UH,
SOMEWHERE AND ANYWHERE,
TO CHECK OUT
A FILIPINO-INSPIRED FOOD TRUCK.
OH, THESE DUDES ARE ROCKIN' IT.
THIS IS GUERRILLA STREET FOOD.
FLYING PIG,
ONE INCH PUNCH.
IT'S KIND OF NICE
COMFORT FOOD.
IT REMINDS ME OF HOME.
ADOBO
AND A CALAMANSI COOLER.
IT'S VERY HARD TO DESCRIBE,
BECAUSE IF YOU SAY,
"FILIPINO STREET FOOD,"
THEY SAY, "WHAT IS THAT?"
I SAID, "YOU JUST HAVE TO COME
OVER TO THE TRUCK AND TRY IT."
IT'S UNLIKE ANYTHING ELSE
IN ST. LOUIS.
PROVIDED BY A COUPLE
OF BUDDIES
WHO BOTH BRING
SOMETHING TO THE TABLE.
(woman) THE OWNERS ARE
BRIAN HARDESTY AND JOEL CRESPO.
JOEL SUPPLIES HIS FILIPINO
FAMILY INFLUENCE...
ADOBO
AND A CALAMANSI COOLER.
AND BRIAN BRINGS
THE CULINARY CHOPS.
I'M PLATING
A CHICKEN ADOBO.
WE LIKE THE SAME KIND OF FOODS.
RUSTIC, SIMPLE FOOD.
SO IT ONLY MAKES SENSE
THAT THEY TOOK
THEIR FAVORITE KIND OF GRUB
TO THE STREETS.
WHEN I SAW THE NEW FILIPINO
FOOD TRUCK WAS GONNA OPEN,
I KINDA STARTED
STALKING 'EM.
(woman) I WOULD GO
DOWN THE STREET,
ONTO THE HIGHWAY
TO CHASE THEM.
AND LOCALS ARE DEVELOPING
WHAT WE'LL CALL A HEALTHY
OBSESSION FOR THIS DISH.
BLUE CRAB CEVICHE
FOR CAROL.
THIS IS JUST AWESOME.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
BLUE CRAB CEVICHE.
LET'S HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT.
FIRST IS THE BLUE CRAB.
HENCE THE NAME?
YES. NEXT UP
WE GOT RED ONION,
SOME SCALLIONS.
WE HAVE, UH, PALM VINEGAR.
NEXT WE'RE DOING
A CALAMANSI JUICE,
WHICH IS NATIVE
TO THE PHILIPPINES.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A KEY LIME,
AND IT'S GOT HONEY
IN IT, TOO.
OH, I WASN'T
EXPECTING THAT.
THAT WAS...
NO? IT'S GOOD.
I WASN'T EXPECTING IT
TO BY SYRUPY.
YOU KNOW, IT DOESN'T
TASTE BAD, BUT, MAN,
IT WAS WAY MORE VISCOUS THAN
I THOUGHT IT WAS GONNA BE.
WHOA.
OKAY, SO NEXT
IS BLACK SESAME OIL,
PAPRIKA, SUGAR,
SOME KOSHER SALT,
AND THEN LAST IS THAI CHILIES.
THEY'RE SMOKIN' HOT,
SO WE DON'T USE A LOT OF 'EM.
MAYBE I SHOULD POP
ONE OF THOSE IN MY MOUTH...
NO, DON'T DO THAT.
AFTER THE VISCOUS ORANGE SYRUP
THAT I JUST GOT A...
THEN WE JUST MIX IT TOGETHER
AND LET IT MARINATE
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR,
AND THEN IT'S READY TO SERVE.
THIS IS AN APPETIZER?
THIS IS SERVED ON TORTILLAS?
YEAH.
THIS IS--WHAT DO WE?
WE JUST CUT SLICES
OF WATERMELON,
AND THEY'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE TREATED LIKE CHIPS.
SUPPOSED TO BE
TREATED LIKE CHIPS,
LIKE, "CORN TORTILLA,
CORN TORTILLA!"
WHOO!
A LITTLE SPICY.
(speaking indistinctly)
THE CRAB IS STILL
IN ITS LUMP STATE.
COME ON.
THE CREATIVE SIDE
OF THE WHOLE THING
IS HOW WELL THE WATERMELON
PAIRS WITH IT.
IT'S A NICE
COUNTERBALANCE.
IT'S ALL SPECTRUMS
OF THE FLAVOR PROFILE.
A CITRUS, VINEGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF SWEET,
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
THAT'S A LITTLE MORE
SOPHISTICATED
THAN I EXPECT TO FIND
OUT OF A FOOD TRUCK
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROAD
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI.
BANANAS.
AND BANANAS IS GOOD.
THE WATERMELON IS JUST
SO UNUSUAL. IT'S MARVELOUS.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT
SUMMERY TIME DISH,
DEFINITELY IN THE TOP TIER
OF FOOD TRUCKS IN ST. LOUIS.
THE WAY YOU MARKET
IS THROUGH TWITTER...
YEP, SOCIAL--
FACEBOOK,
AND COOL GRAPHICS.
EXACTLY.
AND A LITTLE STREET CRED
NEVER HURTS.
DO YOU HAVE A ONE-LINER FOR ME?
GIVE ME SOMETHING.
YOU GOTTA HAVE, LIKE,
A LITTLE...
EASILY, I APPROACH. THIS FOOD,
DAWG, IT AIN'T NO JOKE.
MY MAN AIN'T KIDDIN',
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT COMES
TO ONE OF MY FAVES--
HAND-ROLLED NOODLES
AND VEGGIES, FILIPINO STYLE.
VEGGIE PANCIT
FOR TIM.
PANCIT?
YEAH, IT'S LIKE FILIPINO
PAN-FRIED NOODLES.
REALLY? YOU'RE GONNA
MAKE THE NOODLES?
YEAH.
MAKE THE NOODLES. YOU GUYS
HAVE NOTHING ELSE TO DO?
I MEAN...
WE LIKE TO MAKE IT
HARD ON OURSELVES.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE GONNA
ROLL OUT THE PASTA DOUGH.
AND THIS WILL BE ENOUGH
NOODLES FOR HOW LONG?
THIS AMOUNT IS LIKE
TWO ORDERS.
ROLL IT UP, AND THEN
WE CUT THE NOODLES.
AND THAT'S IT.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN PASTA.
AND WE COOK IT
IN CHICKEN STOCK.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW WE'RE COOKING
WITH GAS.
OLIVE OIL IN THE PAN,
RED CHILIES,
AND YELLOW JALAPEÑOS,
SCALLIONS,
SHIITAKE MUSHROOMS...
SNAP PEAS, YELLOW SQUASH.
I LIKE THE VEGGIE
SELECTION.
A LITTLE BABY BOK.
YEP.
WHOO-HOO. AND LOOK AT
THESE BEAUTIFUL NOODLES.
MADE BY HAND,
BLANCHED,
ICE BATH--
STOP THE COOKING PROCESS,
AND NOW THEY GO IN?
EXACTLY.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
CHICKEN STOCK
TO RECONSTITUTE IT,
LET THOSE NOODLES
SOAK IT UP.
AND THEN SOME
COCONUT MILK.
LOOK AT THAT, THOUGH.
HANDMADE NOODLE.
MM-HMM. NICE AND AL DENTE
AND TENDER.
IT'S A GOOD-LOOKING DISH.
READY TO ROCK?
YEAH.
♪♪
MM-HMM, MM-HMM.
(mumbling)
THE FRESH CRUNCHY VEGGIES,
WARM 'EM UP,
BRING OUT THEIR FLAVOR.
THE HANDMADE PASTA--
AND I DOCTORED MINE UP
WITH A LITTLE FISH SAUCE
FOR THAT EXTRA TANG,
AND JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SRIRACHA
'CAUSE I LIKE IT SPICY.
NICE JOB.
PANCIT.
THE NOODLES AND THE VEGGIES
ARE NICE AND CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE WHAT
MY GRANDMOTHER USED TO MAKE.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK...
CALAMANSI COOLER,
ONE INCH PUNCH.
THE BOYS AT GUERRILLA
STREET FOOD ARE READY
TO QUENCH YOUR THIRST.
ONE INCH PUNCH?
YEAH, LIKE BRUCE LEE,
LIKE, THE ONE INCH PUNCH.
HUH?
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
PRETTY GOOD?
♪♪
AT GUERRILLA STREET FOOD
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
OWNERS BRIAN HARDESTY...
I'M PLATING
A CHICKEN ADOBO.
AND JOEL CRESPO...
HI, WHAT CAN
I GET YOU?
ARE SERVING THEIR TAKE
ON FILIPINO FAVORITES.
CHICKEN ADOBO.
VEGGIE PANCIT.
THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT IT
THAT MAKES MY MOUTH WATER.
THEY'RE EVEN MIXING UP
MOUTHWATERING DRINKS
INSPIRED BY THE KIND
OF FRUIT COCKTAIL
YOU'D FIND ON THE STREETS
OF MANILA.
ONE INCH PUNCH.
ONE INCH PUNCH?
YEAH, LIKE BRUCE LEE,
LIKE, THE ONE INCH PUNCH.
HUH?
SO IT'S JUST
PINEAPPLE JUICE,
BLACK CURRANT JUICE.
CAN'T FIND THAT
ON THE STORE EVERY DAY.
NO, WE GET IT FRESH
WHEN WE CAN,
BUT OTHERWISE WE GET IT
ALREADY JUICED. HONEY.
SUGAR.
AND THEN A LITTLE
COCONUT MILK
AND FRESH MINT.
REALLY?
YEP. JUST LEAVE IT IN WHOLE.
THE FLAVOR WILL COME OUT.
IT'LL STEEP IN THERE,
YEAH.
(punch)
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
PRETTY GOOD?
MMM. WOW,
THAT'S REFRESHING.
IT'S THE PINEAPPLE,
THEN YOU GET THE BERRY,
AND YOU GET THAT ACIDITY.
A LITTLE CREAMY WITH
THE COCONUT MILK.
AND THEN YOU GET THE CREAMINESS,
GET THE RICHNESS OF IT.
YEAH.
OH. I'M TELLING YOU
SOMETHING--
FUNKY LITTLE CHAIRS,
SITTING ON THE STREET,
CARS BLOWING BY, YOU GUYS MOVING
A MILLION MILES AN HOUR...
FLYING PIG.
ALL THAT, AND THEN WASH IT DOWN
WITH A LITTLE ONE INCH PUNCH.
YOU GOT IT.
SURE THERE'S NOT, LIKE,
FOUR TRUCKS BEHIND YOU?
GOTTA DIG IT.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
THANK YOU.
REALLY WELL DONE.
SO THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVOR-TOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
MY GIRL RACHAEL RAY--SHE GAVE
YOU PROPS ABOUT YOUR BURGERS?
YES. I GOT A HUG
ON THE SHOW.
A HUG, REALLY?
YEAH.
DON'T THINK YOU'RE
GETTING THAT FROM ME.