HEY THERE, I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
(imitating blender)
IT'S A WICKED-TASTY TOUR
OF THE GREAT STATE
OF MASSACHUSETTS.
OH, CAN YOU FEEL
THE MAGIC?
IN BROOKLINE
JUST OUTSIDE OF BOSTON...
(speaking indistinctly)
THE HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
DREAMING UP NEW WAYS...
OHH.
TO SERVE UP SANDWICHES.
KNOW WHAT THAT SAYS?
TREADMILL, BABY.
AND IN EAST BOSTON...
THIS IS LIKE
THE GATEWAY TO GREAT FOOD.
THE ITALIAN JOINT...
YEAH.
DISHIN' UP THE SAUCE...
GONNA MAKE
MY FAMOUS MARINARA.
FAMOUS?
FAMOUS.
THE SEA...
'CAUSE THERE'S NOTHING
LEFT IN THE OCEAN NOW?
AND A SEAT AT THE TABLE...
NOT BAD.
WITH THE MAYOR OF BEAN TOWN.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
NOW WHEN YOU ROLL OUTSIDE
OF BOSTON GOING WEST
ABOUT 2 OR 3 MILES,
ONE OF THE FIRST CITIES
YOU'RE GONNA HIT IS BROOKLINE.
IT'S HOME TO THE BIRTHPLACE
OF J.F.K.,
A COOL MAGAZINE CALLED
"COOK'S ILLUSTRATED,"
AND A ROCKIN' LITTLE SANDWICH
JOINT KNOWN AS CUTTY'S.
I GOT A RABE T.J.
GOING ON THE PRESS.
TWO BEEFS FOR HERE.
THIS IS NOT
YOUR AVERAGE SANDWICH JOINT.
IT'S VERY SPECIAL.
IT'S--IT'S VERY UNIQUE.
A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM
DOING IT THEMSELVES.
AND ACCORDING TO THE LOCALS,
CHARLES AND RACHEL KELSEY
ARE NO ORDINARY CHEFS.
THEY'RE ARTISTS.
WE LOVE SANDWICHES.
WE COULD NEVER FIND EXACTLY
WHAT WE WERE LOOKING FOR.
SO THEY OPENED UP
THEIR OWN SHOP IN 2010
JUST DOWN THE STREET
FROM THEIR OLD JOB.
IT ALL STARTED AT
"COOK'S ILLUSTRATED" MAGAZINE.
I LOVE THAT MAGAZINE.
WE WORKED TOGETHER
ON THE BOOK TEAM.
NOW THEY'RE WORKING TOGETHER
ON THE SANDWICH TEAM.
I HAVE THE ROAST BEEF 1000.
HAVE YOU TASTED
THIS SANDWICH?
NO, I HAVEN'T.
LET ME TO JUST--
GO RIGHT--GO--PLEASE.
BE MY GUEST.
(laughing) NO.
ROAST BEEF 1000's
MY FAVORITE THING.
WHY'D YOU CALL IT
THE ROAST BEEF 1000?
'CAUSE IT'S FROM
THE FUTURE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE, UH, SPICE SALT RUB--
BLACK PEPPERCORN,
DRIED THYME,
GROUND NUTMEG...
(whistles)
PINK PEPPERCORNS,
DRIED BAY LEAVES.
THESE ARE CLOVES
THAT WE TOAST.
MY BOAT MOTOR.
SALT GOES IN THE BOWL.
DUMP IN
OUR SPICE MIXTURE.
GIVE IT A LITTLE TASTE.
(coughs)
POTENT STUFF.
OH, YEAH.
SO NOW LET'S TRIM
THE BEEF CHUCK ROLL.
THAT'S ENORMOUS. THIS IS,
LIKE, A BRONTOSAURUS.
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE OFF
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF THE FAT,
SO IT'S NOT TOO FATTY.
SO WE'RE GONNA FLIP IT OVER
AND WE'RE GONNA TIE IT.
(grunting)
NOW WE'RE GONNA
RUB IT DOWN.
OKAY.
YOU PUT GLOVES ON
OR A HAT?
NO, I JUST GO BARE.
(growls)
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA RUB IT DOWN
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
OKAY.
IN THE FRIDGE 24 HOURS.
COOK IT EVENLY, AND WHAT
TEMPERATURE AND HOW LONG?
WE START ON 500.
AFTER ABOUT AN HOUR,
WE DROP IT DOWN TO 300,
AND IT GOES TWO
TO THREE HOURS AFTER THAT.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR CRISPY SHALLOTS
FOR THE ROAST BEEF 1000.
WE'VE GOT SHALLOTS. WE SLICE
'EM UP, PUT 'EM IN THE POT.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR COLD OIL.
HOW MUCH OIL ARE YOU
PUTTING IN THERE, SON?
A COUPLE INCHES
FROM THE TOP.
I'M GONNA TURN IT
TO MEDIUM-HIGH.
THEY'RE GONNA COOK FOR ABOUT
45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR.
AT A CERTAIN POINT,
ALL THE MOISTURE DRIVES OFF.
YOU SCARE THE MOISTURE
OUT OF 'EM.
AND THEY FRY UP.
THEN WE SKIM 'EM OUT,
AND THEN THEY'RE GOOD TO GO.
NICE MEDIUM-RARE.
MMM. OH, EXCELLENT.
GOT A BLACK PEPPER
BRIOCHE BUN.
GIVE THAT A LITTLE TOAST
IN THE PANINI PRESS.
THAT'S SO
YOU DON'T SQUISH IT?
YES.
VERY NICE.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S A THOUSAND ISLAND
WE MAKE IN-HOUSE.
COPIOUS AMOUNTS
OF BEEF.
YEP, SHARP CHEDDAR CHEESE.
HIT IT WITH SOME SHALLOTS.
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT SAYS?
TREADMILL, BABY.
IT'S OUTSTANDING.
THAT HERB SALT RUB
IN THAT--MMM, KILLER.
THE ONLY THING
THAT I GOT TO TELL YOU
THAT I THINK
YOU SHOULD CHANGE--
IT SHOULD BE
THE ROAST BEEF 1 MILLION.
(cash register bell dings)
ORDER UP!
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING. IT'S GOT
FLAVOR. IT'S GOT CRUNCH.
(woman) THEY'RE JUST
A LOT OF FUN.
IT REALLY COMES THROUGH IN THEIR
CREATIVITY AND THEIR FOOD.
WHERE THERE ARE NO LIMITS.
A LOT OF MY FRIENDS
ARE VEGETARIANS,
AND I'M LIKE, "THERE'S
PLENTY OF CHOICES FOR THAT."
YOUR FAVORITE SANDWICH?
BROCCOLI RABE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE TOMATO JAM
FOR OUR RABE T.J. SANDWICH.
RABE T.J. SANDWICH?
RABE TIJUANA.
WHO IN THE HECK
IS RABE TIJUANA?
T.J. IS SHORT FOR
TOMATO JAM OR TIJUANA.
ALL RIGHT, HIT IT.
SO I GOT FRESH TOMATOES--
CORED, HALVED.
I'VE GOT DISTILLED
WHITE VINEGAR, FRESH GINGER,
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF SALT,
FRESHLY GROUND BLACK PEPPER,
RED CHILI FLAKE,
CUMIN THAT WE TOAST IN-HOUSE
AND GRIND UP OURSELVES,
AND THEN A WHOLE
LOT OF SUGAR.
(imitating blender)
I HAD TO GET IT STARTED.
IT'S GONNA GO
INTO OUR NONSTICK POT
TO REDUCE FOR SEVEN TO EIGHT
HOURS AND TURNS INTO JAM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THE GARLIC OIL
THAT GOES IN THE BROCCOLI RABE
FOR THE RABE TIJUANA.
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL,
RED CHILI FLAKE,
I'M GONNA ADD
SOME GARLIC.
GIVE IT ABOUT
10 OR 15 MINUTES.
THE GARLIC JUST TURNS,
LIKE, A STRAW COLOR,
LIKE, LIGHT GOLDEN BROWN.
SO WE HAVE SOME
BLANCHED BROCCOLI RABE.
AND TAKE THAT OIL
THAT WE MADE--DUMP THAT.
RIGHT IN.
AND THEN WE GOT
SOME SHARP PROVOLONE HERE.
OH, THAT IS NICE
AND SALTY AND TANGY.
MIX THAT UP, AND THAT'S
GONNA GO ON OUR SANDWICH.
THAT, THE TOMATO JAM,
AND WHAT KIND OF BREAD?
SESAME TORTA ROLL--
A MEXICAN-STYLE TORTA ROLL.
YEAH.
ARE YOU--YOU'RE MAKING IT
SOUND LIKE TORTOISE.
THE TORTA ROLL
IS FROM MEXICO.
(Charles) WE ADD SOME OF
THE SAUTéED BROCCOLI RABE
MIXTURE, FRESH MOZZARELLA.
(Guy) LOCAL?
YEAH, THIS IS FROM
CONNECTICUT.
SALT, THERE'S YOUR SALT.
SALT ON THAT
CHEESE, RIGHT?
THE OLIVE OIL.
THE T.J. JUST ONLY
ON THE TOP BUN.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
SO WE'LL LET THAT GO?
LET THAT GO,
AND WE'LL COME BACK IN A FEW
MINUTES AND GIVE IT A TRY.
MMM. I'M NOT A HUGE
BROCCOLI RABE FAN,
'CAUSE IT'S A LITTLE BIT
BITTER FOR ME,
BUT IN THIS INSTANCE, BECAUSE
YOU TOOK THE BROCCOLI RABE
AND SMOTHERED IT
IN GARLIC OIL,
THE CREAMINESS
OF THAT MOZZ
WITH THE SWEET
AND THE ACID OF THE JAM--
A LOT OF TEXTURE,
A LOT OF FLAVOR,
A LOT OF CHEW,
A LOT OF BITE.
GREAT SANDWICH.
GOT A RABE T.J.
COMING OFF THE PRESS.
NEVER HAD
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
I THINK THIS ONE WINS.
(Guy) YOU ARE A SANDWICH
MAGICIAN OR A SANDWICH MAESTRO.
THERE'S GOT TO BE A NAME
FOR YOU, SO WE'LL--WE'LL
COME UP WITH IT WHEN WE COME
BACK. WHAT ARE WE MAKING NEXT?
A PORK FENNEL.
WE'RE HANGING OUT AT CUTTY'S
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF BOSTON.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE BIT.
GREAT SANDWICH.
AWESOME.
WELCOME BACK. TRIPLE "D"
HANGING OUT HERE AT CUTTY'S
IN BROOKLINE
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF BOSTON,
AND WE'RE HANGING OUT WITH
THIS GUY--THE SANDWICH WIZARD.
A.K.A. CHARLES KELSEY,
WHO WITH HIS WIFE RACHEL
HAS BUILT UP
QUITE THE FOLLOWING.
I WORSHIP THESE GUYS.
IT'S SORT OF A CULT.
I GOT A RABE T.J. UP.
THE SANDWICHES ARE AN EXPERIENCE
IN AND OF THEMSELVES.
FROM THE OFFBEAT...
(man) THIS IS
THE OLIVE CARROT SALAD.
TO PORK DONE EVERY WHICH WAY.
(Charles) I GOT A HAM DIJON.
GREENS BACON UP.
PORK FENNEL.
GARLIC PURéE, ROASTED PORK,
PICKLED FENNEL.
IT'S THIS PERFECT
MARRIAGE OF TEXTURE
AND FLAVOR AND CONSISTENCY,
AND OF COURSE, YOU KNOW,
WHO DOESN'T LIKE GARLIC PURéE?
THIS IS THE PORK BUTT. WE'RE
GONNA RUB IT DOWN WITH OUR SALT.
WE'RE GONNA
CROSSHATCH THIS FAT,
SO THAT SALT MIXTURE
CAN GET IN.
THOSE ARE GENTLE,
LITTLE SLICES.
BUTTERFLY KISSES.
AND AGAIN, OUR MAGICAL RUB WITH
THE 600 POUNDS OF BAY LEAVES,
THE TOASTED CLOVES.
(laughing)
IS THIS GONNA GO FOR
24 HOURS IN THE COOLER?
THIS ACTUALLY GOES
FOR 48 HOURS--
TENDERIZES IT
JUST THAT MUCH MORE.
ROAST IT OFF.
500 DEGREES.
AFTER ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO,
WE KICK IT DOWN TO 300 DEGREES
AND LET IT FINISH. WE'RE
GONNA MAKE THE PICKLED FENNEL
FOR THE PORK FENNEL
SANDWICH.
I'M GONNA START WITH
DISTILLED WHITE VINEGAR,
A COUPLE QUARTS
OF WATER,
SUGAR, SALT...
THIS IS INTERESTING.
YELLOW MUSTARD SEED.
A LITTLE SPICE?
UH, YEAH, A LITTLE
CHILI FLAKE,
DRIED BAY LEAVES, A BUNCH
OF SLICED FRESH GARLIC.
BRING THIS UP TO A BOIL,
AND THEN POUR IT
OVER OUR SLICED FENNEL.
(bell dings)
THERE IT IS.
LET THAT SET ON THE FENNEL
FOR HOW LONG?
INDEFINITELY.
SO IT'LL JUST
STAY IN THAT BATH...
IT'LL JUST STAY
IN THAT BATH.
AND YOU'LL JUST PULL FROM THAT
WHEN YOU MAKE THE SANDWICH?
YEP.
OHH.
WHAT YOU JUST SAID.
REST IT IN
THE REFRIGERATOR OVERNIGHT.
THROW IT UP ON THE SLICER,
SLICE IT UP.
ALL RIGHT,
WE GOT OUR PORK.
SO WE'RE GONNA TOAST UP
OUR, UH, SESAME TORTA ROLL.
ALL RIGHT, READY?
UH, ROASTED GARLIC PURéE.
WE DON'T HOLD BACK.
NO HOLDING BACK.
(laughs)
PORK GOES ON, NICE HANDFUL
OF THE PICKLED FENNEL,
AND THEN WE GOT A SQUEEZE
OF SOME FANCY OLIVE OIL.
THAT MAKES, LIKE, A LITTLE
SALAD DRESSING ON THERE
WITH THE PICKLES
AND THE--
AND THE VINEGAR THAT'S
ALREADY IN THE--
Sí, SENOR.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, MAN. JUST WHEN I THINK
I'VE SEEN IT ALL,
I'VE NEVER HAD
A BANDOLERO BANDITO
MAKE ME A PORK SANDWICH
RIGHT OUTSIDE OF BOSTON.
THIS IS A FIRST.
THE PORK IS COOKED PERFECTLY,
AND THE FENNEL SALAD ON TOP,
ABSOLUTELY
THE PERFECT COMPLEMENT.
THE CRUNCH, THE VINEGAR
COUNTERBALANCING
THE SALTY BUTTERINESS
OF THE FAT OF THE PIG--
PROFOUND. DON'T GIVE ME
THE CLINT EASTWOOD EYES.
(laughing)
AWESOME SANDWICH.
MUCHAS GRACIAS.
YEAH, DE NADA.
(Rachel) PORK FENNEL.
PRETTY OUTRAGEOUS.
IT'S THE ONLY ONE
I'VE EVER ORDERED.
OUT OF ALL
THE SANDWICHES,
YOU'VE ORDERED
THE SAME ONE EACH TIME?
EVERY SATURDAY
I HAVE THIS ONE.
EVERYTHING'S DELICIOUS.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYTHING
THAT I DON'T LIKE.
AND I NEVER GET TIRED OF IT.
THIS IS
SANDWICH-PLUS-PLUS.
I LOVE THE SCRATCH-MADE
INGREDIENTS.
I LOVE THE CREATIVITY
OF THE MENU.
YOU'RE SETTING THE TONE FOR WHAT
YOU WANT PEOPLE TO EXPERIENCE,
AND I'M GONNA TELL YOU,
WHAT I TRIED--OUT OF BOUNDS.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT...
FUN TIME.
WE'RE ROLLING
INTO EAST BOSTON...
EAST COAST
ITALIAN INDULGENCE.
FOR SOME OFF-THE-HOOK...
I GOT MY FISH GUY.
ITALIAN SEAFOOD.
THIS WILL ALSO INVOLVE
ME SLEEPING IN THE CAMARO
DOWN THE STREET AT A PARK,
JUST LIKE USUAL.
♪♪
SO HERE I AM
ON THE EAST SIDE OF BOSTON.
NOW LAST TIME I WAS HERE,
I WAS EATING SOME DYNAMITE
ITALIAN FOOD AT RINO'S,
BUT I DON'T WANT YOU
TO GET THE WRONG IMPRESSION.
IT'S NOT JUST ALL
ITALIAN FOOD HERE.
I MEAN, THIS IS LIKE
THE GATEWAY TO GREAT FOOD.
YOU'VE GOT KOREAN, VIETNAMESE,
COLOMBIAN, PAKISTANI,
I MEAN, YOU NAME IT, SO WHAT
AM I IN THE MOOD FOR TODAY?
(record needle scratches)
AH, I'M SORRY, IT'S ITALIAN.
THIS IS
ITALIAN EXPRESS PIZZERIA.
ORDER UP.
THEY'RE FOOD IS JUST
UNBELIEVABLE.
SAUSAGE CACC. AND ZITI.
IT'S FANTASTIC ITALIAN FOOD.
JUST LIKE MY MOM'S COOKING.
ALL RUN BY JIM IANNUZZI
AND JONATHAN HARKER,
A COUPLE OF LONGTIME BUDDIES
WHO GREW UP
WORKING IN THE KITCHEN.
(Jim) JONATHAN
HITS THE GYM.
JONATHAN LOOKS GREAT,
TAKES CARE OF HIMSELF WELL,
AND I WORK A MILLION
HOURS A WEEK.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THAT'S NICE, JONATHAN.
THEY MUST BE DOING
SOMETHING RIGHT,
'CAUSE THESE DUDES HAVE BEEN
FILLING THE JOINT SINCE 2002.
WHERE'D YOU LEARN
TO COOK?
MY GRANDMOTHER.
DIG IT.
YEP, NONNI.
ALL THE THINGS ITALIAN
GRANDMOTHERS ARE KNOWN FOR,
LIKE FETTUCCINI
AND HOMEMADE MARINARA,
WHICH ARE THE BEDROCK
OF THE HOUSE FAVORITE...
FRUTTI DI MARI, HERE IT IS.
TOPPED WITH LOADS
OF FRESH SEAFOOD.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
MY FAMOUS PASTA SAUCE MARINARA.
FAMOUS?
FAMOUS.
OKAY.
EVERYTHING HERE
IS FAMOUS.
I'LL TAKE, UH,
EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
I'LL LET THIS GET A LITTLE WARM.
ADD FRESH CHOPPED ONIONS.
GET THE EQUALIZER OUT.
MIX THIS UP.
JUST GONNA LET THOSE
BROWN JUST A LITTLE BIT.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR FRESH CHOPPED--
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC.
STARTING TO SMELL GOOD?
FANTASTIC.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR SAUCE.
AND A LITTLE WATER, TOO.
SOME SALT...
(whistles)
PEPPER, FRESH CHOPPED BASIL.
STIR IT UP.
AND JUST LET IT GO
LOW AND SLOW.
FOR THREE HOURS.
MAGIC'S GONNA HAPPEN.
WE'RE GONNA STEAM
OUR CLAMS.
OKAY.
WE HAVE OUR MUSSELS
AND OUR LITTLENECKS.
SOME WHITE WINE,
TURN THE HEAT ON.
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK,
THE FARM-RAISED MUSSELS.
ALL RIGHT, THERE WE GO,
AND THE LITTLENECK CLAMS.
AND A LITTLE COVER.
THAT'S IT.
LET THEM STEAM OPEN.
WE'RE GONNA START
OUR SAUCE--
OUR BUTTER.
DOES YOUR FAMILY
OWN A DAIRY?
WHAT'S UP WITH THE COPIOUS
AMOUNTS OF BUTTER?
BUTTER TASTES GOOD.
FRESH CHOPPED GARLIC,
SOME WHITE WINE,
CHICKEN STOCK.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN
WE DO. THEN WE WANT TO TAKE
OUR DELICIOUS MARINARA.
ALL RIGHT, NOW TAKE
SOME SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
TAKE SOME FRESH CHOPPED ONION,
AND SOME CRUSHED RED PEPPER.
WE'RE GONNA COVER IT.
THESE ARE DONE.
OKAY.
WE'RE JUST GONNA
DRAIN THE JUICE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW I'M GONNA
TAKE MY SHRIMP, CALAMARI.
LET'S JUST LET THAT COOK
FOR A COUPLE SECONDS.
NOW THE HANDMADE
SEMOLINA FETTUCCINI.
THAT'S RIGHT,
IN MY NICE SALTED WATER.
ALL OF IT?
YEAH.
MUSSELS AND LITTLENECKS
IN HERE.
IT'S LIKE ITALIAN
WEDDING PASTA.
THEN IT'S GONNA BE
ENOUGH FOR 18 PEOPLE.
HOW'S THAT LOOK SO FAR?
RIDICULOUS.
GET MY PLATE READY.
IS THAT ENOUGH?
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S A MEAL
RIGHT THERE IN ITSELF.
RIDICULOUS.
ONE OF THE MOST
POPULAR DISHES HERE.
REALLY? I COULDN'T
UNDERSTAND WHY.
'CAUSE THERE'S NOTHING
LEFT IN THE OCEAN NOW?
THAT'S... (laughs)
FRESH CHOPPED BASIL.
♪♪
MMM. SEAFOOD'S
COOKED PERFECTLY.
CALAMARI, SUPER TENDER.
PASTA'S GOT
NICE BITE TO IT.
YOU HAND-MAKE IT ALL.
YOU BUY THE SEAFOOD FRESH.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN PASTA.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN SAUCE.
YOU COOK IT TO ORDER.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
THIS WILL ALSO INVOLVE
SOME TYPE OF
ME SLEEPING IN THE CAMARO
DOWN THE STREET AT A PARK,
JUST LIKE USUAL.
DYNAMITE.
YOUR NONNA, SHE SHOULD BE
SUPER IMPRESSED.
YEAH, NONNI
WOULD BE VERY HAPPY.
IT'S HOT AND SPICY, SO IF YOU
LIKE HOT AND SPICY, THIS IS IT.
IT'S THE VALUE, THE FOOD,
AND JIM AND JONATHAN.
THEY HAVE IT ALL.
ALL THE WAY TO CITY HALL.
THE MAYOR SHOWS UP.
HE EATS HERE.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
ROLLED EGGPLANT MENINO.
IT'S LUNCH WITH THE MAYOR.
(whispering)
THE MAYOR OF BOSTON.
THIS IS THE BEST.
THESE GUYS DO IT RIGHT.
THEY DO IT RIGHT.
PLUS...
HADDOCK MARGARITA.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
SO MUCH FUN...
EATING THIS FISH.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
YEAH.
FUN FISH,
NEXT ON TRIPLE "D."
WHAT ARE YOU LOOKING AT?
I'M ON THE EAST SIDE OF BOSTON
AT A REAL-DEAL ITALIAN JOINT
CALLED
ITALIAN EXPRESS PIZZERIA.
HOW REAL-DEAL, YOU ASK?
WELL, LET'S JUST SAY THE MAYOR
MR. TOM MENINO
TENDS TO ROLL UP FOR LUNCH,
BUT BEFORE WE HIT
THE EGGPLANT PARM,
HE'S LOOKING FOR A LITTLE FAVOR
THAT INVOLVES THE '68.
BORN AND RAISED BOSTON?
BORN AND RAISED
IN HYDE PARK.
CAN'T BEAT THAT.
WHAT IS ONE OF
THE UP-AND-COMING NEIGHBORHOODS
WE HAVEN'T BEEN TO?
WELL, I THINK ONE OF
THE UP-AND-COMING NEIGHBORHOODS
REALLY IS THE WATERFRONT.
THAT'S WHERE THE NEW
BOSTON'S BEING DEVELOPED.
WE HAVE SEVERAL NEW
RESTAURANTS DOWN THERE--
THE ONES THAT THE GUYS WHO LIVE
IN THE CITY WOULD GO TO.
THIS IS COOL. I APPRECIATE
YOU TAKING A CRUISE WITH ME.
ANYTIME, HEY.
EGGPLANT?
LET'S GO IN.
NICE.
ROLLED EGGPLANT MENINO.
(Guy) SO TELL ME ABOUT
GOOD EGGPLANT PARM.
WELL, IT'S, UH,
GOOD CHEESE, GOOD SAUCE,
AND NICE AND TENDER
EGGPLANT.
THIS IS THE BEST.
THESE GUYS DO IT RIGHT.
THEY DO IT RIGHT.
NOT BAD.
THAT'S GREAT.
NICE AND TENDER.
IT IS VERY GOOD.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT EATING
IN THESE NEIGHBORHOODS?
THEY'RE MOSTLY
MOM-AND-POP,
AND THEY'RE FROM THE COUNTRY
THAT SERVE THE FOOD.
THESE GUYS HAVE
FAMILIES FROM ITALY.
IT WASN'T CREATED
BY GOING TO SCHOOL
OR BY READING TEXTBOOKS.
THEY ACTUALLY DID IT.
OR LEARNED FROM THOSE WHO DID.
(Guy) YOUR GRANDMA MADE
MARGARITA HADDOCK?
(Jim) NONNI USED TO MAKE
THIS WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
HADDOCK MARGARITA,
ROASTED POTATOES.
THIS IS SOME OF THE FRESHEST
HADDOCK YOU'RE GONNA GET
RIGHT FROM OFF THE COAST
HERE IN MASSACHUSETTS.
HADDOCK MARGARITA.
IT'S FUN AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S FUN.
I CAN TELL.
(laughs)
TELL 'EM. YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE SO MUCH FUN...
EATING THIS FISH.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
YEAH. LET'S GO.
HADDOCK IS A FISH YOU FIND
A LOT ON THE EAST COAST.
IT IS.
I GOT MY FISH GUY.
YOU GOT TO HAVE A FISH GUY.
THE FISH GUY. YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S START
MAKING SOME HADDOCK.
SO WE GOT
FILLET OF HADDOCK.
BEAUTIFUL FILLET.
FUN TIME.
WE'RE GONNA DREDGE THE FISH
IN THE FLOUR. HOW'S THAT?
THE FLOUR. SEASONED?
NOPE, JUST PLAIN
WHITE FLOUR.
OKAY.
POUR THE OLIVE OIL
IN THE PAN.
OKAY.
LET THAT GET
A LITTLE WARM.
THEN WE'RE GONNA TAKE THE FISH
AND COVER IT IN THE EGG.
PUT THIS RIGHT
IN THE HOT OIL.
OKAY.
I'M GONNA TAKE THE OTHER,
DIP IT IN THE FLOUR,
THE EGG.
THIS IS THE WAY
YOU'D EAT IT AT HOME?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY. NONNI USED
TO MAKE THIS WHEN WE WERE KIDS.
SHE USED TO SAY, "EAT THE FISH.
IT'S GOOD FOR YOU."
WHILE THIS IS COOKING UP HERE,
WE'RE GONNA GET IT GOLDEN BROWN.
WE'RE GONNA START
OUR SAUCE.
OKAY.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR BUTTER, A PINCH OF SALT,
A PINCH OF BLACK PEPPER.
THIS FISH IS FUN.
I'M HAVING A BALL.
FUN FISH.
NICE, CRISPY, BROWN
EGG BATTER.
COMING OUT PERFECT
RIGHT THERE.
YEAH, IT LOOKS IT.
WHITE WINE
AND CHICKEN STOCK.
OKAY.
GONNA TAKE SOME, UH, LEMON,
SQUEEZE THE LEMON IN HERE.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE'RE
GONNA TAKE THE--
SO THREE SAUTé PANS
FOR ONE DISH.
ONE DISH. IT'S WORTH IT,
THOUGH, ABSOLUTELY.
WHATEVER YOU SAY, BOSS.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA START
OUR PAN-ROASTED POTATOES.
THIS IS EXTRA VIRGIN
FROM ITALY.
WE GOT OUR NICE BUTTER.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL ME
THIS ENTIRE DISH
IS GONNA INVOLVE
NO GARLIC?
NO GARLIC IN THIS.
NONE.
NO. OUR POTATOES.
I'M GONNA SEASON 'EM
WITH SALT, BLACK PEPPER.
THIS FISH IS DONE.
BEAUTIFUL, HUH? LOOK AT THAT.
ISN'T THAT PERFECT?
RIGHT IN THIS SAUCE.
OKAY.
BEAUTIFUL.
THERE WE GO.
I'M JUST GONNA COVER THIS
FOR A COUPLE MINUTES.
NOW I'M GONNA
TAKE SOME PAPRIKA,
I'M GONNA PUT THIS ON TOP
OF THESE BEAUTIFUL POTATOES.
JUST MIX 'EM AROUND
A LITTLE BIT.
TAKE THE FISH.
WOW, IT'S JUST ABOUT
READY TO FALL APART.
YEP.
OHH!
ALMOST.
GO, GO, GO, GO.
I'M GONNA CALL LEON
IF THIS DOESN'T--
OHH.
OHH. IS THAT A PROBLEM?
THE RUSSIAN JUDGE
GIVES HIM AN 8.
COVER THAT WITH SAUCE
AND POTATOES, IN MY OPINION.
OH, THERE YOU GO.
SO NOW WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BIT OF OUR JUICE.
EXTRA JUICE RIGHT THERE
FOR THE DANCE.
THAT IS A LITTLE
SIDE ORDER OF POTATOES.
SO IF I EAT ALL THIS,
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
GIVE ME A RIDE BACK.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW
WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO IS
WE GOT TO FINISH THIS OFF
WITH SOME LEMON SLICES,
A LITTLE FRESH
ITALIAN PARSLEY.
AND THIS IS HOW
YOUR GRANDMA WOULD MAKE IT?
THAT'S IT.
THAT HOW NONNI WOULD DO IT.
NO GARLIC.
NO.
YEAH, THAT FRESH
HADDOCK--PRIMO.
ALL OF OUR SEAFOOD
IS FRESH AS CAN BE.
I'M AT THE MARKET
7:00 EVERY MORNING.
ARE YOU, SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
IT'S TENDER, NOT A REAL
STRONG FISH FLAVOR,
BUT A NICE LITTLE COATING
THERE WITH THAT EGG WASH.
JUST ENOUGH THAT
IT SOAKS UP THE SAUCE.
ENOUGH LEMON,
DOESN'T TAKE IT OVER.
YEAH.
IT'S PUT TOGETHER RIGHT, MAN.
TASTY POTATOES.
EAST COAST ITALIAN
INDULGENCE.
THERE YOU GO.
PACKAGE DEAL.
THANKS, JIMMY.
THANK YOU.
VERY TENDER.
IT FLAKES PERFECTLY.
THE LEMON ADDS A NICE TOUCH
OF FLAVOR. IT'S PHENOMENAL.
IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
ONCE YOU START EATING IT, YOU
CAN'T STOP. IT'S DELICIOUS.
I GOT TO TELL YOU, MAYOR,
THE WAY WAS RAISED
AND WHAT I LIKE TO EAT
AND THE ENVIRONMENT I WANT
TO BE IN IS A JOINT LIKE THIS.
I WANT TO FEEL
COMFORTABLE--
FEEL COMFORTABLE
AND ENJOY THE GOOD MEAL.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY FEEL
THE LOVE THEY HAVE,
BECAUSE THEY WANT YOU
TO COME BACK.
THEY WANT YOU TO COME
BACK TO THIS PLACE.
NOT GONNA FINISH THAT?
I'M GETTING
RIGHT AFTER IT.
I JUST DIDN'T WANT TO EAT
IT ALL WITH YOU HERE.
I FIGURED YOUR DETAIL
WAS GONNA TAKE ME OUT.
OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
SIT DOWN AND RELAX.
ALL RIGHT.
DON'T GET NERVOUS.
TRIPLE "D" WITH
THE MAYOR OF BOSTON.
♪♪
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY--
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT WEEK
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
(Charles laughing)
NOT WEARING IT CORRECT.
OH.
(laughing)