HEY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
LET'S START THINGS OFF.
IT'S A FAMILY AFFAIR...
PAY ATTENTION.
OF AWESOME FLAVORS.
THAT SHOULD BE
THE TAG LINE.
IN MEMPHIS, TENNESSEE...
“DIVE,”
SAID THE CAPTAIN.
THE MOM AND POP
PLUS THREE BOYS...
IT SAID “3 ANGELS”"
YOU MEANT 3 DEVILS.
OH, IT'S VERY
TONGUE IN CHEEK.
LAYING DOWN...
LOOK AT THE JUICE
JUST DRIPPING OUT.
A FRIED CHICKEN ULTIMATUM...
THE BEST FRIED CHICKEN
IN MEMPHIS.
TIME-OUT.
YOU'RE GONNA GET BOTH YOU AND ME
IN A LOT OF TROUBLE ON THAT.
IN HALEIWA, OAHU--
YEP, THE NORTH SHORE...
WHAT, ARE YOU WAVING
GOOD-BYE TO IT?
EVERYBODY'S CHIPPING IN...
YOU GOT TO SEE THIS.
AND GETTING FLY
WITH THE THAI...
I'M GONNA DROWN
IN MY OWN DROOL.
AND IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
GUIDE US
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
THE ITALIAN/GREEK JOINT...
YOU HAVE AWARDS.
YOU'VE WON
BEST ITALIAN RESTAURANT
AND BEST GREEK RESTAURANT.
THAT'S RIGHT,
WE HAVE.
WITH TWO BROS GOING LOCO...
(mumbles)
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
WITH A ST. LOUIS STAPLE...
(normal voice) I SAID,
“THAT'S RIDICULOUS.”
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE “D.”
♪♪
SO I'M HERE
IN THE HISTORIC BROAD AVENUE
ARTS DISTRICT OF MEMPHIS.
WOW, THAT'S A MOUTHFUL.
SPEAKING OF MOUTHFUL,
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
YOU'LL GET AT THIS JOINT,
WHERE THEY'RE SERVING UP A FRESH
TWIST ON AMERICAN CLASSICS.
THIS IS 3 ANGELS DINER.
TWO PIECE, TWO VEG,
PICK IT UP, PLEASE.
MY FAVORITE PLACE TO EAT
IN MEMPHIS.
(woman) IT'S GOT
A LITTLE HIPSTER FUNK
WITH OLD SOUTHERN CLASSICS.
THAT SHOULD BE
THE TAG LINE.
MOM-AND-POP KIND OF PLACE.
MEET MOM AND POP--
REBECCA AND JASON SEVERS,
SEASONED RESTAURANT OWNERS
WHO RAN AN UPSCALE ITALIAN
JOINT FOR A DECADE.
IN 2010, THEY BECAME
THEIR OWN BOSS
AND WENT KID-FRIENDLY
WITH A COMFORT KICK.
IT'S NAMED 3 ANGELS
AFTER THEIR 3 BOYS.
YOU SAID "3 ANGELS."
YOU MEANT 3 DEVILS.
OH, IT'S VERY
TONGUE IN CHEEK.
(boing)
YOU CAN BRING KIDS, AND YOU CAN
EAT MORE DOWN-HOME FOOD.
IT'S MEATLOAF AND BURGERS
AND FRIED CHICKEN.
THE BEST FRIED CHICKEN
IN MEMPHIS.
(whistles)
TIME-OUT. WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET BOTH YOU AND ME
IN A LOT OF TROUBLE ON THAT.
AND THIS IS
THE FRIED CHICKEN?
YES, SIR.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE
A BRINE?
YES, SIR.
EQUAL OR ALMOST EQUAL PARTS
OF SUGAR AND SALT?
A LITTLE BIT MORE SALT
THAN SUGAR.
ALL WE'RE DOING--
INTO SOME WARM WATER
AND LET IT DISSOLVE.
AND THEN WE'RE TAKING THAT
AND HITTING IT WITH THE ICE...
YES, SIR.
TO COOL IT DOWN
SO WE DON'T POACH LE CHICK-OHN.
IT'S ALL ICE ICE BABY.
OH.
THEN YOU JUST, YOU KNOW,
MAKE SURE IT'S ALL SUBMERGED.
OKAY.
KEEP IT COVERED,
PUT IT IN REFRIGERATION...
YES, SIR.
AND LET IT SIT THERE
AND BRINE TEN HOURS.
THEN WE'LL PULL IT OUT,
CUT IT DOWN,
AND START MAKING
SOME FRIED CHICKEN?
YES, SIR.
JUST, YOU KNOW...
SIMPLE, YOU KNOW...
I'M A WING
OR A THIGH GUY.
REALLY?
YEP.
I'LL EAT WINGS ALL DAY.
I LOVE IT.
AIN'T NO THING
BUT A CHICKEN WING.
NOW IS
THE CHICKEN FREE-RANGE?
YES.
I KNOW YOU CAN PROBABLY TELL
JUST FROM MY SWAGGER,
BUT I'M
A CHICKEN RANCHER...
(chickens clucking)
(laughs)
YEAH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE OUR
DREDGE--ALL-PURPOSE FLOUR...
GOT IT.
SALT, BLACK PEPPER,
GARLIC AND ONION,
LITTLE CAYENNE.
LITTLE HEAT, LITTLE COLOR.
OKAY.
JUST GET IN THERE
AND MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
OKAY, SO CHICKEN
IN THE FLOUR.
JUST SOAK UP
SOME OF THAT FLOUR.
GIVE ME--
YOU WANT A LITTLE
MICHAEL JACKSON?
YEAH.
GIVE ME SOMETHING.
A LITTLE SLIDE?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
HUH, DID YOU SEE THAT?
THAT'S A KITCHEN SLIDE.
I MEAN,
GIVE ME A SPIN.
BRING MY CARDBOARD,
AND I'LL START KNOCKING IT OUT.
WE JUST DREDGE 'EM A LITTLE BIT.
I JUST WANT TO DUST.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
DREDGE 'EM IN BUTTERMILK,
AND THEN WE'RE REALLY
GONNA GET IN THERE.
AND THEN HIT 'EM
IN THE FLOUR AGAIN.
BREASTS FIRST.
I WANT
TO REALLY ABUSE--
PACK IT ON THERE.
I MEAN, THAT'S THE WHOLE POINT,
IN MY OPINION, OF FRIED CHICKEN.
I'M TRYING TO BREAK DOWN
THE CHICKEN A LITTLE BIT..
YOU'RE TENDERIZING IT
A LITTLE BIT.
SO IT'LL BE SOFTER--MM-HMM--
TO HAVE A CRUNCH,
SOMETHING THAT'S
GONNA GIVE YOU SOME FLAVOR.
YOU'RE MAKING, LIKE,
A CHICKEN BISCUIT.
WHEN I SAY I WANT A LOT,
I MEAN, THAT'S A GOOD BIT.
THAT'S CRUST-IFIED.
CANOLA OIL, 300 DEGREES--
DROP THOSE IN.
DREDGE THE THIGHS,
PUT THOSE IN.
WE GO IN ORDER--
BREAST, THIGH, LEG, WING.
“DIVE,”
SAID THE CAPTAIN.
BY THE TIME THE WINGS ARE IN,
IT'S ABOUT FIVE MINUTES.
♪♪
TURNIP GREENS.
FROM MISSISSIPPI.
WHITE ONION, JALAPEÑO,
WHITE BALSAMIC VINEGAR.
THOSE TURNIP GREENS ARE AS
FLAVORFUL AS ANY YOU'LL FIND.
LOOK AT THAT.
LOOK AT THE JUICE
JUST DRIPPING OUT.
THE BRINE KEEPS IT THERE.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S WHAT WE WANT.
(laughs)
TENDER. REAL FLAVORFUL.
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE BUTTERMILK ACID.
PERFECT AMOUNT OF DREDGE.
(crunching) GREAT CRUNCH.
IT'S JUST THE KIND
OF FRIED CHICKEN YOU WANT.
HERE IS YOUR CHICKEN.
I LOVE IT.
THEIR CHICKEN'S AMAZING.
IT'S PERFECTLY CRISPY
ON THE OUTSIDE.
IT'S SO JUICY IN THE MIDDLE.
IT'S NOT DRY.
I'LL NEVER
GET SICK OF IT.
EVERYTHING
ON THE MENU'S GREAT.
I HAVEN'T FOUND ANYTHING
I DIDN'T LIKE.
ELVIS, I BELIEVE, WOULD SAY
THIS PLACE IS GENUINE.
OPEN-FACE
CHICKEN SANDWICH.
ECLECTIC ALL-AMERICAN MIX
OF FOOD.
BUT YOUR PRINCIPLES
ARE SCRATCH-MADE...
EVERYTHING FRESH.
VEGETARIAN/VEGAN
IF YOU CAN.
MM-HMM.
YOU MAKE IT
A FAMILY ENVIRONMENT
WHERE PEOPLE WILL FEEL GOOD
ABOUT BRINGING THEIR KIDS.
RIGHT.
HOW MAD ARE YOU GONNA BE AT ME
WHEN THIS PLACE BLOWS UP,
AND YOU CAN'T GET
A SEAT IN HERE?
WE'LL BRING
OUR OWN CHAIRS.
AND FORKS.
WE'LL BE GOOD.
THEY GOT IT.
UP NEXT...
THIS IS
MY FAVORITE KIND OF FOOD.
WE'RE HEADING
TO THE NORTH SHORE OF OAHU...
THE FLAVOR JETS
ARE TURNED ON.
YOU CAN HEAR THE...
(imitates beeping)
FOR A TRIPLE OVERHEAD TASTE...
HOLY MOLY.
OF THAILAND.
YOU WISH YOU WERE HERE.
♪♪
IF YOU'VE EVER BEEN
TO THE ISLAND OF OAHU,
MOST LIKELY YOU'VE BEEN
TO THE NORTH SHORE.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE TALKING
BIG WAVES AND GREAT SURFING.
SO YOU'RE CRUISING THROUGH
THE TOWN OF HALEIWA,
AND THE INEVITABLE QUESTION
COMES UP--WHERE DO I EAT?
WELL, DON'T WORRY,
I GOT THE INSIDE TRACK
ON A GO-TO JOINT.
THIS IS OPAL THAI FOOD.
PAD THAI SHRIMP.
THE FOOD'S MAGNIFICENT. I MEAN,
IT'S SUPERGOOD THAI FOOD.
EGGPLANT STRING BEAN.
IT ALWAYS HAS GREAT FLAVOR,
ALWAYS DIFFERENT TEXTURES.
IS THIS SOME OF THE BEST FOOD
YOU'LL FIND ON THE NORTH SHORE?
IT IS THE BEST FOOD.
THIS IS
THE BEST FOOD.
DOING CHICKEN WING.
I THINK IT'S ALL THE LOVE
THAT GOES INTO IT BY OPEL.
THAT'D BE BANGKOK NATIVE
OPEL SIRICHANDHRA...
THERE WE GO.
WHOSE NORTH SHORE PIPE DREAM
STARTED WITH A FOOD TRUCK
AND GREW INTO
THIS 13-SEAT JOINT
TUCKED INTO A SHOPPING CENTER.
I JUST LOVE THE DYNAMIC HERE.
HIS WHOLE FAMILY
RUNS THE RESTAURANT TOGETHER.
INCLUDING HIS WIFE AOY
WHO COOKS RIGHT ALONGSIDE HIM.
OPEL, TABLE "B" IS READY.
EVEN HIS BOY LIO
GETS IN ON THE ACTION.
YOU HELP, TOO?
YEAH, BUSBOY/SERVER.
BUSBOY “SLASH” SERVER,
IN CASE YOU DIDN'T PICK IT UP.
AND CUSTOMERS
ARE KEEPING LIO BUSY
ORDERING THIS TOP SELLER...
(Opel) PAD THAI SHRIMP.
A THAI CLASSIC LOADED
WITH NORTH SHORE WHITE SHRIMP.
AMAZING.
IT'S VERY SPICY AND FLAVORFUL.
AND I HAVE NEVER
BEEN DISAPPOINTED.
SO THE FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA
START OFF WITH IS THE PAD THAI?
PAD THAI.
LET'S GO.
YOU GOT TO SEE THIS.
YOU GOT
THIS HIGH B.T.U. BURNER.
I MEAN, THIS THING
IS SMOKING HOT.
I'D HAVE THIS RIGHT NEXT
TO MY BED IF I COULD.
READY?
YEP, LET'S HIT IT.
FIRM TOFU, EGG.
PICKLED RADISH?
PICKLED RADISH.
A LITTLE BITE, A LITTLE VINEGAR
FROM THAT, OKAY.
THEN YOU DO THE SHRIMP.
NOODLES.
BUT DID YOU COOK THOSE NOODLES
AHEAD OF TIME?
WE ACTUALLY
HYDRATED THEM.
SO YOU JUST SOAKED THEM
IN SOME WATER.
NOW THEY'RE COOKING IN THERE
A LITTLE BIT.
EXACTLY.
PALM NECTARS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DO
TAMARIND.
TAMARIND'S A BIG PLAYER
IN THAI FOOD, CORRECT?
YES. FISH SAUCE,
PAPRIKA--JUST A TOUCH.
NOT HOT?
NOT HOT.
GREEN ONION.
BEAN SPROUTS.
I'LL TELL YOU RIGHT NOW,
I GET FLY WITH THE THAI.
COULD YOU GO ANY SLOWER?
YOU'RE KILLING ME.
I'M GONNA DROWN
IN MY OWN DROOL.
LIME, PEANUTS.
NOW--
WAIT.
HUH?
YOU GOT
TO TASTE THE FOOD,
AND THEN SQUEEZE
THE LIME.
I THINK
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
BRING THE--
IT'S HOT, THOUGH.
OH, REALLY? WHAT, ARE YOU
WAVING GOOD-BYE TO IT?
MMM.
(laughs)
SECOND STAGE.
SECOND STAGE?
YES, SIR.
YOU REALLY GOT TO WORK. YOU GOT
TO CHEW THROUGH THIS NOODLE.
THE CRUNCHY BEAN SPROUTS.
THE SWEETNESS
FROM THE PALM NECTAR.
I WANT THE THIRD STAGE.
NOW YOU NEED
A CHILI.
AH, AH, AH.
MIX IT.
NOW YOU TRY IT.
NOT OVERLY COOKED,
EVERYTHING STAY CRISPY,
FRESH.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
THAT'S JUST WHAT
I WAS GONNA SAY.
I'VE BEEN TO THE NORTH SHORE
A LOT OF TIMES.
I'VE NOT HAD A CHANCE
TO THAI THIS.
OH, I'M GLAD
YOU TRIED IT.
WHEN MY WIFE FIRE ME,
I'M GONNA COME WORK FOR YOU.
YOU--LISTEN, I'M GONNA--
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAID
ABOUT YOU?
LISTEN, I'LL GET YOU
A PLANE TICKET TONIGHT.
IT'S DELICIOUS. I MEAN, I DON'T
KNOW HOW ELSE TO EXPLAIN.
I'VE HAD IT MANY DIFFERENT
PLACES, BUT I LOVE IT HERE.
HE'S JUST REALLY CREATIVE WITH
EVERYTHING HE COMES UP WITH.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU WANT
ON THE MENU,
YOU JUST TELL HIM WHAT YOU LIKE,
AND HE'LL MAKE YOU SOMETHING.
YOU CUSTOM-MAKE THEM
A DISH?
YES.
I REALLY WANT
TO BRANCH YOU OUT.
OKAY. (laughs)
SO IF YOU'RE A REGULAR,
AND IT'S TIME TO ORDER,
OPEL'S DEFINITELY IN CHARGE.
HE KNOWS WHAT YOU HAD LAST TIME,
AND HE WON'T LET YOU ORDER
THE SAME THING OVER AND OVER.
SO, OF COURSE,
OPEL TAKES ONE LOOK AT ME
AND KNOWS RIGHT WHERE TO GO.
GLAZED GARLIC CHICKEN WINGS,
CLASSIC STYLE.
SO THIS IS
A CLASSIC THAI DISH.
YES.
OKAY,
HOW DO WE START?
FRY THE CHICKEN WINGS,
NO BATTER.
SO THE WINGS ARE COOKING.
NOW WHAT?
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE SAUCE.
THE SAUCE IS GONNA BE
GARLIC-BASED WITH CHILI.
A WHOLE BOAT OF GARLIC.
LOTS OF GARLIC.
YOU KNOW, I HAVE A RESTAURANT
CALLED JOHNNY GARLIC'S,
AND I DON'T USE THAT
IN ONE DISH.
NOW WE'RE GONNA PUT
CHILI PASTE,
JUST AS MUCH
AS WE PUT THE GARLIC.
FOR THOSE SIX WINGS?
MORE OR LESS.
OKAY.
OKAY, WHAT'S NEXT?
VEGETABLE BROTH.
HIT IT.
LET IT COOK
ALL TOGETHER.
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
LIGHT RICE SOY.
PALM NECTARS.
(whistles)
SO YOU MAKE THE SAUCE
A DAY AHEAD OF TIME
TO LET
ALL THE FLAVORS MARRY.
EXACTLY.
AND NOW
WE'RE READY TO GO...
IN A HOT PAN.
LET IT COOK.
PUT SOME MORE FRESH GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA DO
THE BASIL.
FIRECRACKER GOLD.
TOO BAD I WASN'T OVER
FOR THAT PART.
I DIDN'T EAT
A CHICKEN WING.
♪♪
LOOK AT THAT--
NICE CRISPY WING,
NOT OVERCOOKED.
HOLY MOLY.
THAT'S THE MOST GARLIC
I'VE HAD ON ANYTHING, DUDE.
TELL SOMEONE WHO'S
GONNA BE COOKING WITH GARLIC.
THEY'RE EXPECTING
A HARSH, RAW GARLIC
BITTERNESS, SOUR, FIRE.
THIS HAS BEEN COOKED
SO NICE AND LOW AND SLOW
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT CHILI PASTE,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE PALM NECTAR.
YOU DO GOT KIND OF
A SPICY, SWEET, SALTY, SOY
BUT BY NO MEANS
THE FIRE-BREATHING
GARLIC DRAGON.
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS
FRIED THAI BASIL--
NICE AND SWEET
AND CRUNCHY...
(laughs)
CLEANSES THE PALATE.
JUMP BACK
INTO ANOTHER WING.
WHAT ARE
YOU LOOKING AT?
YOUR TATTOO.
OH. I JUST THOUGHT YOU WERE
SEEING IF MY GUT WAS GROWING.
NO. (laughs)
(laughs)
THIS WAS THE BOMB.
THANK YOU.
BUT DON'T WORRY.
IT AIN'T OVER YET.
COMING UP...
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO BEGIN.
OPEL'S GOT ME EXPANDING
MY TAKE...
LARB? LARB? LARB?
LARB.
ON THAI.
GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
LIKE IT?
MY MIDDLE NAME'S LARB NOW.
(laughs)
WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE IN HALEIWA
ON THE NORTH SHORE OF HAWAII
AT OPAL THAI FOOD.
OPEL THE MAN IS GONNA
INTRODUCE US TO LARB?
LARB? LARB?
LARB.
LARB. BUT JUST--L-A-R-B BUT JUST
DON'T PRONOUNCE THE R SO MUCH.
YEP.
OKAY.
LET'S START THINGS OFF.
PREHEATED THE PAN.
PUT THE PORK INSIDE.
SO WE'RE NOT GONNA SEASON
THAT MEAT IN THERE AT ALL?
NOT AT ALL.
BECAUSE THE PORK
HAS ITS OWN FLAVOR.
AND THEN
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO
IS JUST ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF VEGETABLE BROTH.
SO WE'RE EATING THIS--
SO WE'RE JUST TAKING HOT MEAT
AND MAKING A SALAD.
WE'RE MAKING THE MEAT
RIGHT THERE.
YEAH. EXACTLY.
THE FLAVOR JETS
ARE TURNED ON.
YOU CAN HEAR THE...
(imitates beeping)
WE GO WITH FISH SAUCE,
FRESH LIME JUICE.
AND YOU
SQUEEZE IT YOURSELF?
YES, WE DO.
PALM NECTARS--JUST A TOUCH.
IT'S LIKE AGAVE?
YEAH,
IT'S A LOT LIKE IT.
VERY SWEET, BRO.
YEAH.
RED ONION, CILANTRO,
GREEN ONION, FRESH MINT,
AND THEN
ROASTED SWEET RICE.
NICE LITTLE CRUNCH
OUT OF THAT.
EXACTLY.
AND HOW MUCH OF THE...
ROASTED CHILI--
THAT'S ABOUT MEDIUM.
IS THAT HOW YOU HAVE IT,
OR HOW DO YOU HAVE IT? HOTTER?
MEDIUM'S GOOD.
OH, THIS LOOKS GOOD.
THE FISH SAUCE OPENED UP.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT LIME JUICE
OPENED UP.
YOU CAN EVEN SMELL
SOME OF THAT CHILI FLAKE
MIXED IN WITH THAT HOT PORK
AND A LITTLE BIT OF THAT BROTH.
ALL THE FLAVORS ARE HUGE,
AND I'M GONNA TAKE THIS
AND WRAP IT IN SOME LETTUCE.
OH! YOU WISH YOU WERE HERE.
LOOK AT THAT.
OH, DUDE.
MMM, OH, OH.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHERE TO BEGIN
IN EXPLAINING
THE FLAVORS.
A LITTLE BIT OF PORK,
A LOT OF FRESH VEGGIES.
WE GOT THE CILANTRO.
WE GOT THE MINT.
WE GOT THE ONIONS, THE CARROTS,
THE CABBAGE, THE LETTUCE,
A LITTLE BIT
OF THE FISH SAUCE.
YOU GET SOME OF
THE BRININESS OF THAT,
SWEETNESS OF THE PALM, AND
A LITTLE BIT OF CHILI IN THERE.
ALL THAT COMES TOGETHER--
OH.
YEAH.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE
KIND OF FOOD--NATURAL FOOD,
HANDMADE FOOD,
FOOD THAT HAS THE RESPECT,
IT HAS THE HISTORY,
IT HAS THE CHARACTER,
IT HAS ALL THESE PIECES.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
LIKE IT?
MY MIDDLE NAME'S
LARB NOW.
WE ALWAYS CALL IT
THE THAI TACO.
IT'S GOOD. IT'S A FINGER FOOD.
IT'S LIGHT, IT'S REFRESHING.
(woman) IT'S WONDERFUL.
IT WAS SPICY AND FLAVORFUL
AND FRESH.
(Guy)
I'M GONNA TELL YOU WHAT,
I LOVE COMING
TO THE NORTH SHORE,
AND YOUR FOOD
HAS JUST SOLIDIFIED
ME COMING FOR
THE REST OF MY LIFE.
THANK YOU.
MY FRIEND, NICE JOB.
THE BOMB, OH!
UP NEXT...
HURRY UP.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
WE'RE HEADED TO THE HILL ON
THE SOUTH SIDE OF ST. LOUIS...
IT'S ITALIAN GREEK.
FOR A LOCAL TWIST...
IT'S A ST. LOUIS
FINGER FOOD.
ON AN ITALIAN STAPLE.
I WOULD PUT THESE UP AGAINST MY
ITALIAN GRANDMOTHER'S RAVIOLI.
YOU SEE THIS?
THIS MEANS, "PAY ATTENTION."
SO I'M HERE ON THE SOUTH SIDE
OF ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
AT ONE OF THE HIGHEST POINTS
IN THE CITY, KNOWN AS THE HILL.
NOW THIS AREA IS LOADED
WITH GREAT ITALIAN RESTAURANTS
AND SPECIALTY STORES,
SO I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
A LITTLE JOINT THAT'S ITALIAN--
YOU THINK I'M GONNA SAY
ITALIAN AMERICAN--
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE THINKING,
ITALIAN AMERICAN,
BUT, NO, IT'S SOMETHING WE DON'T
SEE ON TRIPLE "D" THAT OFTEN.
IT'S ITALIAN GREEK.
OWNED BY TWO BROTHERS,
THIS IS ANTHONINIO'S TAVERNA.
EURO PIZZA.
IF YOU GO GREEK, YOU'RE GONNA
GET THE BEST OF EVERYTHING.
WE'VE BEEN TO ITALY.
IT COMPARES TO THE ITALIAN
WE HAD OVER THERE.
IT'S A RIGHTEOUS MIX
THAT ANTHONY SCARATO
AND HIS BROTHER ROSARIO
WERE BORN INTO,
WITH THE GREEK COMING FROM MOM
AND THE ITALIAN FROM POP.
WE JUST TRY
TO DO EVERYTHING
LIKE YOU'RE COMING
TO MY HOUSE FOR DINNER.
THAT'S OUR MOTTO--
FAMILY.
FAMILY FEE.
AND IT ALL CAME TOGETHER
IN 2004
IN AN AREA KNOWN FOR
ITS HISTORY AND ITS COOKING.
I NOTICE OUT THERE ON THE WALLS,
YOU HAVE AWARDS.
YOU'VE WON BEST
ITALIAN RESTAURANT
AND BEST GREEK RESTAURANT.
RIGHT, WE HAVE,
WE HAVE.
NOT MANY PEOPLE
GET TO DO THAT.
IT'S PRETTY NEAT.
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT AN APPETIZER
THAT'S ROCKING
A THIRD INFLUENCE...
TOASTED RAVIOLIS.
THE CITY ITSELF.
IT'S A ST. LOUIS
FINGER FOOD.
UNCOMMON TO FIND
OUTSIDE OF THIS AREA.
ANYBODY FROM ST. LOUIS
WHO SAYS THEY HAVEN'T HAD
TOASTED RAVIOLIS--I DON'T KNOW
WHAT ROCK THEY LIVE UNDER.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
TOASTED RAVIOLI.
A LITTLE GROUND BEEF.
GROUND BEEF...
RICOTTA CHEESE.
A LITTLE RICOTTA,
PECORINO ROMANO.
DO YOU SPEAK GREEK?
UH, I ONLY KNOW--
BLACK PEPPER.
BLACK PEPPER, SALT--
UH, YOU KNOW,
A LITTLE HERE AND THERE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO GET
YELLED AT IN GREEK.
I KNOW HOW TO GET YELLED AT
AND CURSED OUT.
SOME ONION.
SOME ONION, RAW ONION.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
WE'RE GONNA--
WE LIKE TO GET THIS
A NICE--NICE PASTE.
PASTE--WE DON'T WANT
TEXTURE IN THIS?
NO, WE WANT IT TO BE SMOOTH,
REAL SMOOTH AND FLUFFY.
THEY'RE LIKE LITTLE
MEAT PILLOWS.
SO THE MEAT PILLOW
MIXTURE IS MADE.
YES.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE--
WITH THAT APPARATUS?
WITH THAT APPARATUS THAT
WE HAD SPECIALLY MADE.
I'VE BEEN TO, LIKE,
EVERY ITALIAN MARKET
ACROSS THE COUNTRY--
I HAVE NEVER SEEN
THIS MONSTROSITY.
OKAY, LET'S DO IT.
OKAY, SO FIRST WE'RE
GONNA TAKE OUR DOUGH,
EVER SO GENTLY.
WHERE DO YOU GET
THE SHEETS OF PASTA?
UH, FRESH FROM A LOCAL
PASTA MAKER.
GOOD. FROM A COBBLER
WOULDN'T BE SUCH A GREAT IDEA.
NO.
AND I'M GONNA BRUSH EGG WASH
ON THERE. GET THE MIXTURE.
SO YOU JUST PLOP
THOSE IN THERE.
YES.
HOW MANY RAVIOLIS YOU GUYS
GO THROUGH A WEEK?
ABOUT 1,500.
SERIOUSLY?
YEAH.
HERE, I'LL LET YOU
TAKE CARE OF IT.
OKAY.
YOU CAN GUIDE US
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
AIR POCKETS.
CAN'T TELL THAT YOU'VE
DONE THIS 9,000 TIMES.
YEAH. CENTER IT, WE'RE JUST
GONNA PRESS IT THERE.
IT DROPS INTO ITS HOLES.
AND DOWN.
AND THEN WE JUST
BRING IT DOWN.
THAT'S IT
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S A BIG RAVIOLI,
BROTHER.
YEAH, OH, YEAH.
IN THE ITALIAN BREAD CRUMBS,
READY TO ROCK 'N' ROLL.
AND OUR MARINARA
IS READY TO ROCK?
YEP. THIS IS
A FAMILY RECIPE.
OH. HURRY UP.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
LET'S DO IT.
OH. THE DOUGH
HASN'T BEEN COOKED.
IT'S GONNA FRY UP,
SO IT'LL BE NICE AND CRISPY.
YES.
HOW WE LOOKING?
READY TO GO?
YEAH, I THINK SO.
THIS IS A REGULAR ORDER?
YEAH, IT'S A BIG ORDER.
YEAH, IT'S A REGULAR
ORDER.
FRESH ROMANO ON THERE.
OH. IT'S GOT
A NICE BITE TO IT,
A LOT OF FLAVOR.
MMM.
WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THE MARINARA,
THE SAN MARZANO,
A TON OF BASIL,
A LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS.
IT WORKS TOGETHER WITH
THE RAVIOLI INCREDIBLY WELL.
YEAH. THANK YOU.
LOOK AT THE AMOUNT OF FILLING
THAT GOES INSIDE OF THIS.
GOOD, OLD-SCHOOL. MMM.
SURE.
(mumbles)
THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
I SAID,
"THAT'S RIDICULOUS."
THE RAVIOLIS--
I WOULD PUT THESE UP AGAINST MY
ITALIAN GRANDMOTHER'S RAVIOLI.
YOU SEE THIS?
DID YOU SEE THIS?
THIS MEANS, "PAY ATTENTION."
LITTLE PILLOWS
OF PERFECTION.
PILLOWS OF--
WOW.
I LOVE COMING TO THESE,
YOU KNOW,
THESE HISTORIC
AREAS OF CITIES
AND SEEING WHERE ALL THIS
ETHNIC INFLUENCE HAPPENED,
AND THE FOOD IS LEGIT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT.
GOOD JOB. THANK YOU, BROTHER.
WHAT ARE WE--
WATCH OUT FOR THESE GUYS!
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT WEEK,
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
I'M ALSO A KENTUCKY ADMIRAL,
WHICH IS ANOTHER...
HOW MANY HATS DO YOU
WEAR, MAN?
WELL, IT'S A LOT. I'M THE
SHERRIFF, I'M THE MAGISTRATE,
THE DEPUTY,
AND THE MAYOR.
MAGISTRATE.
JUST GET THAT STRAIGHT.