I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
On this trip...
Ah!
...I'm hitting the exit...
Keep going. Keep going.
Okay. We're good. We're good.
...for some
savory sensations...
This is all
100% made here.
...in Williamsburg, Brooklyn.
Brother, I'm gonna
tell you something --
You've got it
going on here.
The real-deal diner...
I like the way you roll.
...serving up some
seriously eclectic combos.
[ Southern accent ]
Now we're gonna cook it
in the country oven.
And in Grandy, North Carolina...
Can I get some music
in the background, please?
...the brewery/farm stand/
restaurant combo...
What in the wild, wild world
of sports was that?!
...with all the tools
of the trade.
Holy shnikey!
Dude!
That was out of control.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
I'm just over the bridge
from Manhattan
in a cool, little neighborhood
known as Williamsburg.
I've heard it described
as kind of like a college campus
just without the college,
so you know they got to have
cool, little joints like
this place -- Jimmy's Diner.
Got The All American
with bacon.
It's heaven on a plate.
Chico Grande.
It's perfect breakfast,
lunch, or dinner.
MAN: Fried chicken.
They fry it just enough,
but they keep it healthy
just enough.
WOMAN: It's all I want to eat
on a weekend morning,
especially if you've been
out late the night before.
FIERI: No worries,
'cause in the morning,
Josh Cohen and Blair Papagni
got you covered...
like they have since 2007
when they opened the joint.
Like that awesome diner
in a college town.
But you guys
have no college.
Oh, that's not true. This is
like the unofficial NYU campus.
NYU's in... [Whistles]
In the city.
This is just
the commuter burb?
Exactly.
COHEN: And Blair made the menu
when she was pregnant.
You do have
fried pickle chips?
With a peanut-butter
milkshake.
You have those?
Absolutely.
Crazy.
Interesting combinations
of ingredients
like pulled pork and eggs
for breakfast.
Boozy milkshakes.
Little Jack
in your milkshake.
That's it.
Give me a membership card.
The skillet apple waffle.
With pancetta and apple
on top.
This meat-candy sensation,
which is brilliant.
What is
a skillet apple waffle?
Well, we're calling this
a skillet,
hence the apples
that are gonna be cooked in it,
and it'll be on top
of a waffle.
And we're gonna have pancetta
in this, also?
Correct.
I like the way you roll.
Gonna put
the pancetta in.
The pancetta --
I blanch first,
take a little of the salt out,
a little bit of the --
And it also
speeds it up a bit.
It does.
Copious amounts of butter.
Then I add our apples.
I'm gonna add
some white sugar --
just a little.
Some brown sugar.
Okay, so, it reduces down.
Now we hit with maple syrup?
Yep.
This is waffles gone wild.
We're gonna do
a little nutmeg, cinnamon.
Then I'm gonna add
a little lemon zest.
It'll cut a little
of the flavor of the sweet
and the fat
of the pancetta.
I like this
pancetta-and-apple idea.
Now we're gonna make
the waffles.
We have AP flour, sugar,
some baking powder, salt.
Mix that up a little bit.
Add some of our buttermilk,
and then the butter,
and vanilla.
I'm gonna add
a little oil.
Thank you, sir.
Keep going. Keep going.
Okay. We're good.
We're good. We're good.
That looks like pudding.
That's it?
No more moisture than that?
It's usually pretty tight.
Okay. So, we have that.
Gonna add a little bit
of lemon zest in it...
...mix...
and there we go.
Really?
So we're putting in pudding.
We have magic.
It's beautiful, huh?
Okay, so, we'll put
the waffle down.
It's Chinese roast pork
and apples.
Look at this. Oh!
Little lemon drizzle.
You and your lemon zest --
I love it.
Part savory, part sweet.
The pork, the salt.
Great waffle --
nice and tender, good crust.
You get a little bit
of the maple syrup in there.
You can definitely taste
that lemon zest,
the essence of the lemon.
Oh!
That's a waffle
that eats like a meal.
Mmm!
Killer job.
Thanks, man.
FIERI:
When we get back to Jimmy's...
Chico Grande's up.
...it's round two...
Forget about it.
...with the Williamsburg take...
The artist formally known
as "picadillo."
...on a Latin staple.
FIERI: "Triple D" is hanging
at Jimmy's Diner
in Williamsburg, Brooklyn, where
Josh Cohen and his wife, Blair,
are cramming
their pint-sized place
with some standout standards.
Skillet waffle up.
Chico Grande.
I've been coming here
for six years,
and I've been so obsessed
with the fried chicken
that I have overlooked
the empanada.
Don't you feel silly now?
Oh, yeah.
I feel like I've wasted
six years of my life.
[ Laughs ]
Chico Grande's up.
MAN: Chico Grande -- It's got
black beans, eggs, empanadas.
It's very, very good.
What are we gonna make?
Gonna make our filling
for the empanadas.
It looks like we have a little
picadillo we're making.
We just call it "filling."
We're not that fancy.
Just gonna put
a little bit of oil in.
The ground beef down.
Yep.
Season.
Onions.
Some cumin,
some chili flake...
...some oregano.
Mix that up a little.
Sweating those onions down.
We get a nice sear
on the meat.
We're gonna put in
some roasted garlic,
some tomato puree...
...green olives
with pimentos.
Great brininess --
the golden raisins.
Yeah.
You made picadillo.
Throw me a little carrot
in there, and we'd be done.
But we don't,
so maybe we're not.
So, maybe we're just pica.
[ Chuckles ]
All right, so,
we cook this down,
everybody's
marrying flavors.
You got all the cast
of characters.
You got the roasted garlic.
Forget about it.
It's money.
[ Laughter ]
Okay, so, our picadillo
is quite delicious
with the golden raisins --
the artist formally known
as "picadillo."
This is the dough.
We're gonna take two of them.
We have a little egg wash.
Is that whole-wheat
empanada dough?
Yeah.
How California of you.
It's very Williamsburg
of me.
Very -- Oh, really?
You got to spend
more time here.
We pan-frying these?
They go right in the fryer --
We call it "country oven."
The country oven?
You never heard that one?
No.
[ Southern accent ]
Now we're gonna cook it
in the country oven.
Country oven --
There we go.
[ Normal voice ]
Let's hit the salsa verde.
We have our cooled tomatillos
and jalapeños.
We take this immersion --
Mixer.
[ Whirring ]
Get a little avocado
to cream it up.
A little avocado,
cilantro, lime.
Little bit of oil.
A little pepper,
a little touch of salt.
Nice.
Okay, that's done.
The empanadas are done.
Drop our eggs in.
We have some black beans
with a little pico de gallo.
We add the potatoes.
Okay, we have some eggs,
empanada.
And last but not least...
Second to last --
a little bit of love.
Brother, I'm gonna
tell you something --
You've got it
going on here.
Add a little
queso fresco.
I love getting that sweet from
those raisins coming through.
Little bit of heat
from the chili flake,
and the kicker always
is the olives, the brininess,
kind of like a little
of that Latin sweet and sour,
and good, chewy
empanada dough.
Mmm!
Dude, and just the fact that
you put it in the country oven.
[ Laughs ]
That guy.
From Brooklyn, right?
"Brooklyn --
the other southern state."
Oui.
Yeah.
[ Chuckles ]
PAPAGNI: Chico Grande.
MAN #1: Flaky, crispy on
the outside, delicious filling.
MAN #2: The salsa verde's
one of the creamiest,
spiciest salsas I've ever had.
Is it not outrageous?
It's perfect.
They killed it.
They totally do.
They're serious about the food.
I love it.
It feels like home.
A little better than home.
It's amazing.
Thanks for coming.
You're nuts. You're crazy.
Coming from you,
that's a compliment.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
to Grandy, North Carolina...
Bingo.
That was the cow's name?
[ Chuckling ]
She's no longer with us.
...where farm to table...
It's right there.
...is mixing
with mad science...
Oh, that's awesome!
...for some righteous flavors.
Mmm.
Whoo! It is coming down.
I'm cruising
on the Caratoke Highway,
on my way from Norfolk down
to Nags Head, North Carolina,
and I'd heard about this place,
where they've got
their own brewery,
their own farm,
their own butchery,
making great sausage, killer
beer, growing their own produce.
And the way the rain's
coming down right now,
this is a perfect time
to stop off
and check out
the Weeping Radish.
I love this place.
I really do.
The food is excellent.
Here's your sausage sampler.
MAN: Oh, the sauerkraut --
They make it right here.
FIERI:
Like they do back in Germany,
where Uli Bennewitz grew up,
and he's been bringing that
same attitude to the Outer Banks
since '06
when he opened the Radish.
The whole idea is to literally
take the product from the farm
all the way
to the restaurant table.
Everything's made
in-house.
FIERI: With the help
of chef Ken Frederick
and German master butcher
Frank Meusel,
these dudes bring
a serious one-two punch,
even when it comes to the soup.
And how about
the baked-potato soup?
What do you think?
Mmm.
Speaking of comfort food.
It's loaded with cheese
and bacon and potatoes.
FIERI:
Did somebody say "bacon"?
We've got a side
of pig here,
and we're gonna go
to all this work
just to get
the bacon out of it
to make
the baked-potato soup?
BENNEWITZ: I'm not. He is.
[ Laughs ]
Can I get some music
in the background, please?
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Whistles ]
We separated the baby back ribs
from the spare ribs.
We actually get the animal
from a farm.
We literally buy
the whole animal.
Oh, he's trimming
those down.
Now we are talking bacon
at this point.
Serious bacon here.
FIERI: That gets a tenderizing
turn in a tumbler overnight,
heads to the smoker
for three to five hours,
then ends up
as killer bacon bits
just waiting to be sampled.
We're gonna make
some baked-potato soup.
All righty.
All right.
Gonna make a little roux?
What are you gonna make here?
We're gonna put milk
in there.
We're gonna whisk in
some all-purpose flour.
We're gonna add our potatoes,
the cheddar cheese.
Beautiful. Next up?
Gonna use
our green onions.
All right, we're gonna add
our bacon bits.
All right.
You better do it before --
Done eating?
[ Chuckles ]
Beautiful.
And sour cream.
So, everybody's
in the pool.
Gonna let it simmer up, and
that is our baked-potato soup.
Word to that.
Bowl it up for you.
There you go.
Okay.
All right.
House-cured smoked bacon --
very nice.
A little bit of cheddar cheese,
green onion.
Crack a little pepper overtop.
Nicely done.
Mmm.
Nice chunk of potato.
These potatoes
are from that field?
Came from
out of the field.
You know what the kicker is?
That sour cream in there.
That gives it
a little bit of twang.
House-cured bacon
inside of it
adds to that whole attitude
that Uli's set in this place.
"Farm to table"
as close as it comes,
especially when it's in your
own back field -- 14 acres.
That's how you do it.
That's good soup, man.
Thank you.
Mmm.
WOMAN: Oh, my gosh.
It's so rich and creamy.
The best flavored bacon.
It tastes like someone
pureed a baked potato.
It does --
a very good baked potato.
Yeah, exactly.
I think it's really cool
to be able to come in
and get a beer
that's brewed here.
FIERI: Tell me about the beer.
How's the beer?
How legit?
Beer's the bomb.
From really light
to really dark,
and lightly hopped
or heavily hopped,
and the cuisine's the same.
Sometimes you can have a salad,
or you could have, like,
a sausage sampler.
FIERI: Or their high-tech take
on a deli classic.
This is my favorite
Reuben sandwich all around.
FIERI: Out of anywhere
you've ever been?
Anywhere I've been,
this is the --
Anywhere you've ever been,
this is your favorite.
This is the best of the best
Reuben sandwiches.
It might be
'cause they're baking the bread,
making the kraut,
and curing their own pastrami.
This is for the pastrami.
Very beautiful
piece of meat.
This is our grass-fed beef,
trimmed down.
Now we're going to
inject it.
When it goes
through the process
of being smoked or being cooked
or whatever you may do,
it's gonna lose moisture, so
this is gonna balance it out.
Bingo.
That was the cow's name?
Yes, it was,
but she's no longer with us.
So, what are we gonna
inject it with?
Water in there, with ice,
then we have celery juice
in there.
The celery juice --
Time-out, time-out.
Celery juice?
Yeah.
We do everything
nitrate-free.
Take celery juice, which,
during the cooking process,
converts to nitrates
anyway.
Natural nitrates.
That's correct.
Just one second.
Okay.
Does this guy remind you
of, like, any crazy scientist
kind of dude making meat, huh?
[ Laughter ]
Anyhow...
So, now we're gonna
take this
and send it through
the "injector-needler"?
Yes, yes.
Oh, this is gonna be good.
Yes. Stand back
because it squirts.
FIERI:
This is not the time
that you want to wear
that necktie to work.
Fire her up.
Okay.
Off it goes.
Gonna wreck its day!
Oh, that's awesome!
Ah!
What a beautiful machine.
What in the wild, wild world
of sports was that?!
Isn't that beautiful?
You pumped it, man.
Now we're gonna have
a tumbler.
That's the next machine
it's going into.
Now we're gonna play
with another toy?
Yes.
It's like a massage machine,
basically.
FIERI: Where the beef gets hit
with a blend of spices
that include paprika,
garlic, and sugar.
So, it stays
in there overnight.
Then it's off to the smoker
for three to five hours.
So, Uli gives you all this,
sets you up for success.
All you have to do
is prepare it, serve it,
and make happy people.
I get all the accolades.
We're making the Reuben?
Yep.
I'll cut some of this off.
Oh, look at that.
Just want to warm that up.
Sauerkraut.
We'll add the cheese.
The bread off of there.
Get our pastrami.
Gonna get a little Thousand
Island dressing on it.
There we go.
House-made bread,
house-made pastrami,
and house-made sauerkraut.
It's right there.
It's big flavor.
It is the real deal. Mmm.
That rye bread's bomb.
This is all
100% made here.
That's what makes it work.
Nice job, man.
Thank you. Thanks.
Really nice job.
There's more to come.
We're hanging out
at the Weeping Radish.
When we come back,
you might see me
eat something that I said
I would never try.
We're hanging out
at the Weeping Radish.
This is Uli, who owns the joint,
and he's going to make...
Sweet-potato liverwurst.
I hate liver.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN: I think people are afraid
of it because of its name.
I think if you called it
something else besides "liver",
more people would like it.
SERVER:
Liverwurst Crostini.
Uli assures me
it's fantastic.
It's great.
It won the Good Food Award.
It's wonderful.
Where was the award given?
San Francisco.
This doesn't look like liver,
thank goodness.
Pork butt?
Pork butt.
That's going to be in
with the liver?
Absolutely.
Cut it with as much
as you can.
Good-looking pork.
Where's it from?
It's from a local farm.
We pick it up ourselves.
We buy only one animal
at a time.
And you use
the whole animal?
Use the whole animal.
Nothing wasted.
Cutting this into small,
manageable pieces that
we'll be able to grind?
We are going to cook it first
and then grind.
Oh, really?
We have a kettle over there.
It's a nitroglycerin
cooker.
A nitroglycerin cooker?
Like, "ba-boom"?
That's the stuff
that's on the outside
that conveys the heat.
Watch out for this guy.
Captain sweet-potato liverwurst
is on fire.
All the meat goes in there
and slow-cooks in there --
very, very slowly.
FIERI:
And while the pork's cooking,
it's time to face my fears.
I don't even want
to look at it.
Ugh.
BENNEWITZ:
Beautiful pork liver.
I'm not kidding you.
That is my Kryptonite, man.
Let's go. [ Chuckles ]
There we go.
[ Gagging ]
Fire in the hole!
Fire in the machine.
[ Whirring ]
Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh.
[ Gagging ]
Oh, that's gnarly!
There we go. Ready.
So, now the roasted chunks
of pork?
That's it.
Fire in the hole!
There we go.
[ Whirring ]
This is a monster, man.
This is a real machine.
Shutting her down.
Shut it down.
That was the meat.
Now comes potatoes.
Sweet potatoes?
Sweet potatoes next.
Cooked or raw?
Raw, raw.
Raw. Okay, here we go.
That's it?
Yep. Okay.
Now we're gonna mix it all
together and make sausage.
We're getting closer.
How much more can we do?
Ol' chopper.
That thing is a monster.
This is
a real machine.
Ready for this?
Okay.
Pork goes in first.
[ Whirring ]
Whoa, baby!
Dynamite!
I thought he was gonna forget
to put the liver in.
Holy shnikey!
Dude!
What do you think?
Is this
for real or what?
That was
out of control.
Now what are we gonna do?
You're going to stuff it.
Mm, just hard to resist
digging into it now.
Look at the forearms
on that dude.
BENNEWITZ:
Okay, Frank, off we go.
FIERI: Oh, he's got
a little knee press there,
then you give it
a little clippy-clamp.
Now, does this ever harden up,
or is it always soft?
Gonna cook it
after this.
Ah.
In the smoker or what?
In the smoker.
We don't use smoke. We just use
the heat to cook.
Just use the heat in it.
Once you cook it in there,
it tightens right up.
FIERI: I got to say,
I'm a bit relieved to see
that he's paired it up
with a homemade pretzel roll.
All right, let's go.
Okay, let's go.
This, right here,
is gonna be an experience.
There you go.
There we go, five pieces.
Okay, now comes the magic.
You don't have to cut it
all open on my accord.
Oh, yes, oh, yes.
You have to suffer for this one.
Look at that. See?
You're already getting excited
over this.
Something you eat a lot?
Ooh.
Absolutely.
There you go.
Just lay that out there.
I put it on there.
There we go.
Okay.
Now need a few onions
on them.
I'm not eating the actual
whole big chunk of liver.
Remember, sweet potatoes,
they're good for you.
What are you --
Dr. Uli now?
[ Chuckles ]
There we go.
All ready to go.
Which one?
Thin one.
[ Laughs ]
I did that just for you.
Couple more onions
on there.
No mustard or anything?
Sure, we got some mustard.
Lusty Monk out of
Asheville, North Carolina.
Beautiful mustard.
Come on.
Where we going?
[ Laughs ]
I just have to get the image
of it squirting out --
Out of your mind.
Yeah.
I understand that.
But I've done that.
The texture --
It's smooth
and creamy and delicious
and great flavor with all
the ingredients you added,
and there's also liver
in there.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN:
Liverwurst Crostini.
It does not overwhelm you
with that liver flavor.
I think it's great.
The food's outstanding.
Thank you.
The sausages, the pastrami,
along with the beer.
You're doing this on 14 acres
and a gigantic warehouse.
I mean, you're like the most
popular guy in your village.
[ Laughs ]
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Just want all
of his good buddies to know
that are gonna be watching
this show
that he does have
makeup on.
[ Chuckles ]
Not me. No need.
This right here --
magic.
[ Laughter ]