I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
This place is gonna be bouncing.
...we're hitting the grill...
Out of bounds.
...with some worldwide flavor...
Wow.
...in Los Angeles California.
There's other magic
in here.
The buddy burger joint...
This is kind of like The Rebels
of Fairfax.
...going Mediterranean
on the lamb...
Look at the juice.
That burger's rock star.
...and fiery on the pulled pork.
It's up in the top 10.
And in Tacoma, Washington...
This is gonna be
good stuff.
...the Belfast-inspired spot
with a taste
for the Middle East...
All righty.
...going way beyond bar food.
We're gonna kabob it up
right now.
From a homegrown take
on kabobs...
Right on.
...to a local spin...
That's outrageous.
...on big-time beets.
Off the chain.
Honestly.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
When I was living down here
in southern California,
I used to cruise up and down
Fairfax Avenue in Los Angeles
to go to work.
It was always an area known
for delis, bakeries,
the farmers market,
and now I guess you can say
it's known for burger joints.
Well, that's since this place
opened up -- The Golden State.
It's an amazing place.
People come from all over
the city to come here.
Burger medium with fries up!
This is the best burger I have
ever had in my entire life.
FIERI:
Pretty high praise for a couple
of restaurant rookies.
Neither of you
had culinary experience?
Nothing that would say,
"Hey, you should go open
a restaurant."
So, lifelong pals
Jason Bernstein and James Starr
ditched the corporate world
to open this joint
and found success
with one simple formula.
We're just trying to, like,
do very clever things
with very good quality
ingredients.
Like grass-fed beef
in their spicy dog,
locally made gelato
in their beer floats,
and fresh ground lamb
for their burger
coming from the farmers market
right down Fairfax.
MAN:
It's got a great lamb taste,
sort of a Mediterranean feel
going on.
MAN #2:
That kind of stands alone
just because they've chosen
to use a different meat,
which brings a different flavor,
and all the ingredients
are fresh.
All right,
what are we making now?
We're gonna season
the ground lamb
for our lamb burger patty.
Hit it.
All right.
We're gonna start with some
fresh chopped mint, parsley.
Our house spice blend.
It's made up
of garlic powder,
onion powder,
and a little bit of oregano.
There's other magic
in here.
But probably not legal
in most states.
Might not be.
[ Laughter ]
Some cumin
and some oregano.
You're taking this,
mixing it up.
You gonna let
these flavors marry?
Yeah, we'll let it rest
for 20, 30 minutes.
Not too long.
Next up?
We're gonna make the yogurt
dill sauce for our lamb burger.
Like a tzatziki of sorts?
It is a tzatziki, yeah.
It's like a variation on that.
Start with some yogurt...
dill...
some mint, some cucumber.
English cucumber?
Persian cucumbers.
We're in L.A., man.
We got to represent.
Lemon juice.
I didn't know
you were Persian.
I'm not.
But I do have some close friends
who are Persian.
Shout out to Sham Shabahain.
All right.
Did you just shout out
on my show?
Yeah.
Please don't hurt me.
A little bit of salt,
black pepper,
and again,
our magical house seasoning.
I want some more yogurt.
Does that need more salt?
Ooh, that's good tang
on that yogurt.
A little
lemon juice helps.
Good to go?
Yeah, I think
we're good to go now.
We're gonna make some hand-cut
roasted sweet potato wedges.
Chop this bad boy up.
We're gonna bake them first,
and then we're gonna
deep-dry them.
Put a little crunch
on the outside.
Exactly Sort of like
that Thanksgiving ham
but crossed
with a french fry.
Dude.
You look like
you're gonna hurt yourself.
Some olive oil.
Salt and pepper.
Toss, toss, toss.
On to the sheet tray.
Now we're gonna go
right in the oven with these.
What temp?
350 for about 45 minutes.
[ Timer dings ]
Bring them out,
let them cool,
and then we'll fry them again
for service?
You got it, man.
Word.
[ Sizzling ]
Let's season the lamb patty
and grill it up.
We're gonna let that thing
sear off
for about three minutes
on each side.
Put some
Gruyère cheese on top,
throw it in the oven,
let it lock all the juices in.
Let's pull the lamb burger
out of the oven.
Got a little bit
of that yogurt dill sauce
that we made earlier.
Lamb patty is next.
Roasted red peppers.
Little bit of arugula on top
and some curry ketchup.
Curry ketchup.
Yes, sir.
And our sweet potato wedges
come out of the fryer.
Put a little bit of salt,
pepper, parsley, toss those up.
There you go.
So, here's the thing
that you get --
great seasoning
inside of the burger.
The herbs, the fresh herbs in it
really make it.
Look at the juice coming out
of the burger.
Not overcooked.
The Gruyère...
nice and creamy on top.
Sweetness of
the roasted red bell peppers
and then that little bit
of that curry ketchup
coming in there in the back
comes together awesome.
This is a real
sweet potato.
It's more like a
Thanksgiving-style sweet potato
in a french fry form.
I'm gonna tell you, man,
that burger's rock star.
Lamb burger with sweet potatoes,
table 10.
It's really unique,
and you can't beat the taste.
The flavor really pops.
These sweet potato fries
are my absolute favorite.
FIERI:
When we come back...
Wow.
...the sun keeps shining
at The Golden State...
It's really hot.
...with a spicy take on some
pulled pork perfection.
I've had a lot
of pulled pork sandwiches.
I know it's hard to tell.
FIERI: We're hanging
at The Golden State
right off Fairfax Avenue
in downtown L.A.
Order's ready.
Table number 4.
A top-shelf burger joint
owned by compadres
Jason Bernstein and James Starr.
How do they rate?
Awesome.
To find it, though, you got to
keep your eyes from blinking.
The location of this place
is really cool.
It's so unassuming.
You wouldn't just, walking up
the street, notice this place.
And when you're grilling up
flavors like this,
you're bound to stand out.
Funky little burger joint
amongst all these delis
and bakeries.
This is kind of like The Rebels
of Fairfax.
From funky decorations
to craft beer on tap
to the outrageous take
on this classic sandwich.
Pulled pork sandwich
in the window!
FIERI:
Topped with pickled jalapeños
and a scratch-made mustard
that'll make you cry uncle.
MAN:
It's really juicy pork.
It's got some jalapeño in it
for some kick.
MAN #2:
Super crunchy and super spicy.
The flavor kind of spikes in
a lot of different directions.
All right, fire it up.
We got the whole pork shoulder
right here.
We have salt, some more
of our house seasoning,
paprika,
and black pepper.
You gonna do a little rub
to this, or...?
Yeah, I usually massage
the thing.
Ohh, massage.
Treat it like
my girlfriend.
There we go.
Next up, we're gonna sear the
pork shoulder on the stovetop.
[ Sizzling ]
Then we're gonna throw in
some chopped onion.
Chopped carrots,
apple cider vinegar,
some fresh beer
off the tap.
And how many beers
do you guys...
...drink a day?
Very nice.
How many do you have
on tap?
We have about 10 beers
on tap.
10 on tap.
Yes, sir.
And a little water.
And some water for good measure,
just to cover.
How long's it gonna go?
It's gonna go
for about seven, eight hours.
On the stovetop.
Yes, sir.
Wow.
All right,
pork butt is cooking.
Yes, sir.
Now what are we into?
Something jalapeño
and delicious.
Yeah, we're gonna pickle
some jalapeños
that we're gonna put
on the sandwich.
Okay.
All right.
We're gonna start
with some mustard seed.
Black peppercorn.
Toast those off.
Bay leaves.
All right, next.
This is L.A.'s finest
filtered tap water.
Apple cider vinegar.
And a little bit of sugar.
We're gonna let that
come to a simmer.
And then we're gonna
pour the brine...
Pour it right over the top.
Let it sit in the fridge
for a little bit,
let the flavors marry.
Now what are we into?
We're gonna make
the hot mustard sauce
that we're gonna use
for the pulled pork sandwich.
Word.
And we're starting off with...?
Dijon mustard, sir.
Ketchup is for wusses.
Some Worcestershire.
Worc-ch-ch-ch-ch-estershire.
Apple cider vinegar.
And this is
cayenne pepper.
That's gonna be strong.
Yeah, it's really hot.
It is pretty strong.
[ Whistles ]
Yeah, it's intense.
But when it's on the sandwich,
it works really well.
Wow.
Take our tongs.
Ooh.
So, all the braising liquid
comes with it?
Yes, sir.
Couple of those broken-down
onions and carrots, as well.
All right.
Pickled jalapeños
and some pickled onions.
And then
we're gonna top it off
with our hot mustard sauce
that we made earlier.
The pork is super moist.
It's got a little Latino side
to it, almost like carnitas.
Really where you start to rock
the house is those jalapeños.
Hey.
I've had a lot of
pulled pork sandwiches.
I know it's hard to tell.
[ Chuckles ]
It's outrageous.
I'm not kidding you.
This is righteous.
I'm so glad you like it.
Well done.
Everything good?
Excellent.
Awesome.
Thank you so much.
You could sell just that.
The meat is, like,
fall-off-the-bone.
I just can't stop eating it.
It's one of the best things
that they do here.
It is one of the best
pork sandwiches I've had.
I mean,
it's up in the top 10.
It's awesome, guys.
It's a great vibe,
it's a great joint.
Get ready to get in line.
This place
is gonna be bouncing.
Up next...
Crazy.
...we're headed
to Tacoma, Washington...
This is gonna be
good stuff.
...for an Irish pub...
Beef kabob.
...with some
Middle Eastern grub.
Off the chain.
Honestly.
I'm here in Tacoma, Washington.
Now, you know when you go
to a new town,
you're always looking for, like,
that road to Flavortown,
you know, that area that's got
all the killer bars
and restaurants?
Well, I'm told this is it --
6th Avenue right by
the University of Puget Sound.
And I hear the joint
you got to check out --
they're serving up
the killer drinks and food --
is this joint, The Crown Bar.
You're gonna get a good meal
every time you come.
It's my go-to place --
casual, neighborhood place.
FIERI:
A little like a place
Chef Charlie McManus remembers
from back home.
So, The Crown Bar
in Belfast
is supposed to be the most
beautiful bar in the world.
It's been there
for 140 years.
A wee bit longer
than this Crown Bar
that Charlie and his wife,
Jacqueline, opened in '07.
We thought
that this place
could be a good ode
to my Belfast roots,
and so we called it
The...
...Crown Bar.
Love Jacqueline and Charlie,
and their food
is always delicious.
How do you describe
the food?
Eclectic, ethnic.
Upscale bar/tavern food.
MAN: Currywurst.
The mushroom quesadillas
are off the chain.
Honestly.
Full of flavor,
really crunchy falafel.
Cheers.
Cheers.                 Cheers.
And the beef kabob.
This beef kabob tastes so good.
Spicy beef with couscous.
MAN: And it's got
a lemon cilantro sauce on it,
cucumber raita,
and a nice grilled pita.
We are making couscous that will
go with our beef kabob.
Couscous.
Big in the Mediterranean.
That's just a bunch
of little pasta.
Equal parts hot water
and couscous.
Whisk the couscous in
so it doesn't clump.
And then curry powder.
A little madras
curry powder.
We let this sit for about 10
minutes to absorb the liquid.
Take some olive oil,
rub it with our hands
so that every little clump
is broken down.
Then we put it into the oven
for 20 minutes.
[ Timer dings ]
It's come out of the oven.
Sprinkle a little bit
more oil on it.
And then just work it
one more time.
And the idea is to make this
light and fluffy.
Fluffy and velvety.
And this is the way they do it
in Morocco.
This is gonna be
good stuff.
Next we make
the raita sauce.
Enraita?
Raita.
All righty.
Take the skin
off this cucumber.
English cucumber, fantastic
with the little seeds.
I'm actually gonna take
the little bits of seeds
that are in there out.
So, I'm gonna slice these.
And then we're gonna
chop them up.
All right.
So...
then I'm gonna let it drain
for about five minutes.
So now we're using
Greek yogurt for this.
There we go.
Little mint, cumin.
Stir that together
a little bit.
The drained cucumber
goes in.
Little bit of salt,
freshly ground pepper.
And there we have it.
Now, this will improve
with flavor as time goes on.
It will. Three or four hours,
it's gonna be perfect.
All right. We're going to make
our Moroccan beef kebab.
Okay.
We've got grass-fed beef,
ground up.
80%/20%.
Yeah, it's about 80%/20%.
Bread crumbs,
ground ginger,
cumin, cayenne, parsley...
cilantro, red onion.
And then we have
non-fat milk powder.
And what it does is hold
that beef together.
I'm gonna mix this by hand.
Salt, pepper.
There's so much flavor
in this.
We're gonna kabob it up
right now.
About a 2 3/4-ounce ball.
Then we're gonna make them
into little bricks.
There we go.
And they are gonna go
on the grill.
We're not gonna put them
on kabobs?
They're gonna get the handle
at the end.
And about seven
or eight minutes to cook.
Very nice.
All right?
We've got couscous,
got the raita,
and I'm gonna skewer up
my kabobs.
Here we have
the charmoula vinaigrette,
Little bits of pita.
Little bit of cilantro
on top.
And there it is.
That's all she wrote.
That's not over-spiced,
by any means.
And the couscous, dude.
Something that simple
done that right -- mm.
This is light and fluffy as
anybody would love to get it.
Tell me
about this sauce on top.
It's a charmoula sauce.
It's the all-purpose sauce
of Morocco.
They use it to marinate
lamb, fish, beef.
So it has cumin, cayenne,
paprika,
lemon, parsley,
and cilantro.
I love
all these components.
This is really nice.
Out of bounds.
It's amazing. It's juicy.
It's full of flavors.
Little bit of curry flavor --
just awesome.
The crust is really flavorful
and gives it a really nice kick.
Really a terrific dish.
FIERI:
And while they're serving up
flavors from around the world,
Charlie knows
there's no place like home.
I love this place.
FIERI:
When we come back...
Beet salad -- the bomb.
The bomb.
The bomb bomb.
FIERI:
I'm hanging at The Crown Bar
in Tacoma, Washington,
where chef Charlie McManus
has connected the dots
between local farmers
and his menu.
Fried chicken.
The food is fresh
and it's local,
and we're supporting
local farmers.
Beet salad up.
I don't typically love beets,
but I love this salad
because the way they make
the beets, they roast them,
but they're still very tender
and juicy.
WOMAN:
Roasted beet salad.
I'm actually the guy that grew
the beets over there.
You're the beet farmer?
Get out!
Yeah.
How awesome.
And what kind of beets
do you grow?
We do mostly
golden and red.
FIERI: Front and center
on this savory salad.
Beet salad, and it's wonderful.
WOMAN:
It's great with the goat cheese
and the fresh local greens.
It's refreshing and delicious.
Love it.
All right, so we're gonna make
a roasted beet salad.
We have golden and red beets
from a local farmer.
We're gonna size the beets,
cut the ends off,
get them ready
for roasting.
There we go.
We have to do them
separately
because the red ones would bleed
in to the golden.
We just set them
in the foil,
little bit of oil --
olive oil.
Get them nice and tight.
Tighten up the ends,
make it a nice packet.
Into the oven with them.
350, come out, cool down.
All right, so now we're gonna
rub the skins off them.
There we go.
Beautiful beets.
Yeah, they are.
Trim the ends.
We're gonna make
a citrus vinaigrette.
Dijon, honey.
Darling.
This is
from our own garden.
This is this year's model.
That's awesome!
It's got
that buttery thing,
a little nutty
at the end.
Then into that,
we whisk champagne vinegar.
Really?
Your own bees?
Yeah. Doing it
for three or four years.
How many bees
do you have?
We had three hives.
Two of them we lost, but one
of them that's operating.
We have 12,000 bees in it.
What happened
to the other two hives?
Just the conditions for bees
are really tough.
Sometimes
they don't make it.
Really?
Yeah.
Because of the climate,
because of pesticides,
things like that.
Lime juice, orange juice,
lemon juice.
And then the zest
of those citrus in there.
Zest it up.
Zest is in!
Now we're gonna whisk some oil
in there, some olive oil.
There we go.
Pinch of salt,
pinch of black pepper.
That's the citrus
vinaigrette.
Mm.
Dig it.
Right on.
Okay, right on.
Next step,
finish the salad.
Red beets...
into the bowl.
Golden beets.
Citrus vinaigrette
to balance that sweetness.
Just work them in there.
And then we have some greens.
They're gonna go in.
Nice bit of greens.
Just a very light dressing.
And the beet salad in this kind
of a funky bar atmosphere --
this is a big seller?
It's a big seller.
We got
a local college here.
The students come in.
There's a lot of vegetarians.
And people like a robust salad
like this.
There's the beets.
And then we finish it with a
little bit of fresh goat cheese.
And there it is --
roasted beet salad.
All right.
Oh, those are good.
The beets are fantastic.
I mean,
they're just so fresh,
and you just get
such great flavor.
Really still some
firm texture to it.
The dressing is very mild on it,
not too heavy.
Little bit of the tanginess
of the goat cheese.
That's outrageous.
The fact
that you're making it
all here in this little kitchen
in this bar,
this is beyond bar food.
Nice job.
Thank you.
And you make
your own honey.
I've never seen that
on "Triple D."
Beet salad -- the bomb.
The bomb.
The bomb bomb.
WOMAN:
Nice and sweet.
You just can't beat it.
Yeah, you --
FIERI: To the locally
grown beets, the vinaigrette,
with the honey that comes
from your house --
I mean,
that's a pretty big
farm-to-table attitude,
my friend.
In a little bar joint
like this?
Exactly.
Crazy.
Thanks for having me.
I love it.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
We're all
in the trust tree here.
Fred Meyer guy, beet farmer,
vegetarians, face-ripper.
I haven't talked to you two
crazies over there yet.
This is like "Twilight Zone"
"Triple D" style.