HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP,
IT'S AN ACROSS-THE-BOARD
TASTE...
WAH. WAH.
OF AUTHENTIC EATS...
WOW!
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI...
COUPLE NICE BIG FAT BUTTS.
HMM. HERE.
THE ROADHOUSE RESTAURANT...
ROADHOUSE.
THAT'S PRETTY FOOD.
RUN BY A REBEL...
THIS JUST DOES NOT
LOOK RIGHT.
IT ISN'T.
ROCKING OUT REAL-DEAL CAJUN...
(man) RED BEANS & RICE.
AND BRINGING TOGETHER THE BEST
OF ALL WORLDS...
THIS IS EVERY BIT
A PULLED PORK SANDWICH
WITH PASTA
INJECTED INTO IT.
AND IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK...
TAKE ME
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
THE LEBANESE JOINT PUTTING
A MAMA'S TOUCH ON FALAFEL...
AH. OOH,
I HAVEN'T SEEN THIS ONE.
AND BIG-TIME BAKLAVA.
I LIKE TO SEE THINGS DONE
IN EXTREMES. THIS IS EXTREME.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪♪
SO HERE I AM IN THE BEAUTIFUL
WEBSTER GROVES AREA
OF ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT--
NOW GET THIS.
IT STARTED OUT AS A LUMBERYARD.
WELL, THEN IT BECAME
A RECORD STORE.
THEN IT WAS A RESTAURANT
A FEW TIMES.
AND NOW RUMOR HAS IT IT'S OWNED
BY A FELLOW U.N.L.V. ALUM.
OH, THEY'RE SERVING UP FOOD
FROM THE BLUES HIGHWAY.
WE'RE TALKING CAJUN, SEAFOOD,
AND BARBECUE.
THIS IS HIGHWAY 61 ROADHOUSE.
(man) SMOTHERED CATFISH,
VooDoo SHRIMP SANDWICH GOING UP.
(woman) IT REALLY HAS
THAT NEW ORLEANS FEEL AND TASTE.
STEPPING INTO THE ROADHOUSE
IS LIKE STEPPING INTO A PLACE
OFF OF BOURBON STREET.
FULL SLAB IN THE WINDOW.
(Guy) ARE YOU BORN
AND RAISED HERE?
BORN AND RAISED
IN ST. LOUIS.
SO YOU HAVE SOME SAY
ON THOSE BARBECUE.
HOW DOES THAT STACK UP?
IT'S THE BEST.
IT'S REAL DEAL.
HOW YOU GUYS DOING?
JUST WHAT I'D EXPECT
FROM FELLOW RUNNIN' REBEL ALUM
BILL KUNZ.
HE'S BEEN ROCKING OUT
THE ROADHOUSE
WITH HIS OWN BRAND OF PARTY
SINCE 2006.
BROTHER, IT IS THE MOST FUNKY,
ECLECTIC, DISORGANIZED--
WELL, ACTUALLY IT'S ORGANIZED.
IT'S ORGANIZED FUNK.
DID YOUR WIFE JUST MAKE YOU
EMPTY YOUR GARAGE?
(laughs)
BBQ SHRIMP DINNER,
RED BEANS & RICE GOING UP.
SO IT'S THE FOOD BETWEEN
ST. LOUIS AND NEW ORLEANS.
YES.
SIN CITY VEGAS,
SIN CITY NEW ORLEANS--
NOTHING PARTIES
LIKE THOSE TWO CITIES.
NOT THAT I WOULD KNOW.
THIS FUNKY APPROACH IS SHOWING
UP IN THE SWEET POTATO PIE,
SMOTHERED PORK STEAK,
AND THIS OFF-THE-HOOK MASH-UP
OF TWO OF MY FAVORITE THINGS...
BBQ SPAGHETTI DINNER
IN THE WINDOW.
(man) IT'S LIKE HAVING
A PULLED PORK SANDWICH AND PASTA
AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
BBQ SPAGHETTI?
BARBECUED SPAGHETTI.
IT'S A LITTLE SACRILEGE.
JUST LOOK AT HIM. "FEEL IT."
LET'S GET STARTED. THIS IS
THE DRY RUB FOR THE PORK BUTT.
YEP.
OKAY.
SEA SALT,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
PAPRIKA,
GRANULATED ONION,
RAW SUGAR,
BLACK PEPPER...
THE KITCHEN SINK.
A LITTLE CAYENNE
FOR HEAT,
CHILI POWDER.
AND AS YOU ALWAYS SHOULD,
A LITTLE DRY MUSTARD.
I'LL WHISK
ALL THIS TOGETHER.
A COUPLE
NICE BIG FAT BUTTS.
HMM. HERE--THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
OH.
OKAY,
SO A LITTLE A.C.V...
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
ADD A LITTLE MOISTURE
TO IT.
HOW MANY OF THESE DO YOU
GO THROUGH A WEEK?
ABOUT 24 OF 'EM A WEEK.
PULLED PORK SANDWICH...
OKAY.
PULLED PORK DINNER,
BBQ SAMPLER.
SAMPLER?
SAMPLER.
BOY, THAT'S--
THAT'S AN '80s TERM.
AND WE HAVE THE SUPER SAMPLER,
TOO, SO THERE.
YOU DIDN'T SAY
SUPER SAMPLER.
I SAID SUPER SAMPLER.
NICE GENEROUS RUB
TO THAT.
MM-HMM.
INTO THE WALK-IN.
FOR HALF A DAY.
THEN WE'RE GOING
TO THE SMOKER.
WHAT TEMPERATURE
ARE WE GONNA RUN THIS AT?
225.
LOW AND SLOW.
FOR ABOUT?
13 HOURS.
PULL IT OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S PULL-APART TENDER, HUH?
LOOK AT THE GREAT BARK ON THAT.
SEE THAT COLOR?
SEE THAT SMOKE PENETRATION?
BUT NOT A TON OF SMOKE.
NO. NO.
NOT OVERSMOKED.
IT'S NOT BURNT ON THE OUTSIDE,
JUST SO YOU KNOW,
AS I SHOVE MY MOUTH
FULL OF IT.
YOU'LL TAKE
THE BEAR CLAWS.
(bear roaring)
THIS IS WHERE WOLVERINE
GOT HIS IDEA, BY THE WAY...
YEAH.
JUST SO YOU KNOW.
HE WORKED IN
A BARBECUE RESTAURANT.
SO YOU'LL SHRED THIS UP.
MM-HMM.
SO NICE AND JUICY,
TON OF FLAVOR.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR
OVER IT AGAIN.
OKAY.
A LITTLE MORE RUB.
A LIGHT DUSTING
OF RUB.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
NEXT UP?
HIGHWAY 61 BBQ SAUCE.
SEA SALT,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE,
A LITTLE CINNAMON,
NUTMEG...
(whistles)
CHILI POWDER,
BLACK PEPPER.
REAL TOMATO KETCHUP.
REAL TOMATO KETCHUP--
33% FANCY.
MUSTARD.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
LIGHT BROWN SUGAR.
ALL RIGHT, SO LET THIS
COOK DOWN HOW LONG?
ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
SO WE GOT
OUR PULLED PORK.
WE'VE GOT OUR PASTA THAT'S--
THAT'S BEEN COOKED AL DENTE.
NOW WHERE ARE WE AT?
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
ADD OUR BBQ SAUCE,
PULLED PORK.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA ADD
OUR PASTA.
THIS JUST DOES NOT
LOOK RIGHT.
IT ISN'T.
OH.
AND TOP IT OFF
WITH THE FABULOUS GARNISH
OF CHOPPED PARSLEY.
NO, ONLY IF YOU RUN IT
AROUND THE RIM. (laughs)
(laughs)
THAT'S ROADHOUSE EATING.
YOU KNOW THAT YOU'RE GOING
TO A ROADHOUSE
WHEN YOU HAVE
NOT MATCHING FORKS.
AWESOME.
THIS IS THE SALAD FORK?
THAT IS
THE ENTRéE FORK...
(laughs)
AND THAT IS
THE ENTRéE FORK.
THE PULLED PORK'S
DYNAMITE.
THE SAUCE HAS GOT
A NICE TWANG TO IT.
THE VINEGAR COMING THROUGH,
GREAT TEXTURE OF THE PORK.
THIS IS EVERY BIT
A PORK PULLED SANDWICH
WITH PASTA
INJECTED INTO IT.
I DIG IT.
YOU GOT THE PARSLEY GARNISH,
THE SUPER SAMPLER.
IT'S ALL '80s HERE,
BABY.
(laughs)
AWESOME.
YOU'RE CLASSIC, MAN.
(woman)
BBQ SPAGHETTI.
THANK YOU.
(woman) IT'S UNEXPECTED,
'CAUSE YOU HAVE THE BARBECUE,
AND A LITTLE BIT OF SPICY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
BUT THAT AIN'T THE ONLY WAY
THIS JOINT'S SPICING THINGS UP.
CajAsian POTSTICKERS
STEAMING.
(man) IT'S GOT ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE
IN IT,
SO IT GIVES IT A GREAT KICK,
MIXED WITH SOY SAUCE,
GREAT FLAVOR COMBINATION.
OH. UNBELIEVABLE.
NEXT UP?
CajAsian POTSTICKERS.
Ca-Asian?
CajAsian.
C-A-J-A-S-I-A-N.
♪ AND BINGO
WAS HIS NAME ♪
FIRE IT UP.
SESAME SEED OIL,
GREEN PEPPER,
CELERY,
ONION.
SWEAT 'EM.
RAW ANDOUILLE SAUSAGE.
SO WHERE ARE YOU
GETTING THAT FROM?
WE'RE FLYING IT IN
FROM NEW ORLEANS.
SERIOUSLY?
YEP.
CRESCENT CITY MEAT COMPANY.
NOW WE GO IN
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF SAMBAL.
SAMBAL.
CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
SEA SALT,
BLACK PEPPER.
EVERYTHING'S
GONNA GET COOKED
IN THE FAT COMING OUT
OF THAT ANDOUILLE.
WHAT HAPPENS
AFTER THAT?
PUT IT IN A BLENDER.
BREAK IT DOWN
EVEN A LITTLE BIT MORE.
BREAK IT A LITTLE MORE.
WE GOT
SOME POTSTICKER SKINS.
(man) OH!
(laughs)
THEN WE'LL STUFF
OUR POTSTICKER SKINS.
A LITTLE EGG WASH,
FOLD 'EM OVER.
ONCE THEY'VE HAD A CHANCE
TO KIND OF SET UP,
THEN WE TAKE 'EM,
HIT IT IN THE SKILLET?
HIT 'EM IN A SKILLET,
A LITTLE SESAME SEED OIL.
GET THE BOTTOMS
NICE AND CRISPY,
AND THEN PUT
SOME CHICKEN STOCK IN THERE
TO STEAM 'EM.
THEY'RE READY.
SO THE DIPPING SAUCE
FOR THE CajAsian POTSTICKERS--
GONNA MAKE THAT
THE CENTERPIECE.
YES, SIR.
AND SCALLIONS.
WELL, I LIKE
THAT IT'S ALL HAND-MADE.
THAT'S GOOD SAUSAGE.
VERY GOOD.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SPICY.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE KICK
TO IT.
MM-HMM.
YOU REALLY PUT SOME TIME
AND ENERGY INTO THAT.
YOU FLY IN THE SAUSAGE.
YOU MAKE THE STUFFING YOURSELF.
YOU HAND-MAKE
THE POTSTICKERS.
WAY MORE THAN I EXPECTED,
MAN.
REALLY?
NICE JOB.
VERY NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
(man) CajAsian POTSTICKERS
IN THE WINDOW.
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE MERGER
OF BOTH ASIAN AND CAJUN.
THAT TASTES LIKE NEW ORLEANS
IN A POTSTICKER.
PERFECT.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WHAT'S THE CRESCENDO?
WHAT ARE WE GONNA HAVE?
RED BEANS & RICE.
WE'RE DOING RED BEANS & RICE
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WE'RE HANGING OUT IN ST. LOUIS
AT HIGHWAY 61 ROADHOUSE.
HIGHWAY 61 ROADHOUSE.
WELCOME BACK.
TRIPLE "D" HANGING OUT
IN ST. LOUIS, MISSOURI,
AT NOT HIGHWAY 62
BUT HIGHWAY 60...
1.
ROADHOUSE.
(laughs)
AND WE'RE NOWHERE NEAR
HIGHWAY 61.
OVER THERE.
NOW WE'VE ALREADY HAD
BARBECUED SPAGHETTI
AND THE CAJUN-ASIAN
POTSTICKERS.
UH-HUH.
AND THIS IS NOW
WHAT ANY GOOD SOUTHERN CREOLE
BARBECUE RESTAURANT JOINT
BETWEEN ST. LOUIS
AND NEW ORLEANS SHOULD HAVE,
AND THAT IS?
RED BEANS & RICE.
WITH SMOKED HAM HOCK
AND ALL.
HAM HOCK AND ALL.
(Bill) RED BEANS & RICE,
ORDER UP.
(woman) THE FLAVOR'S
REALLY GREAT.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT SPICY
AND A LITTLE BIT SMOKY.
IT MAKES ME FEEL
LIKE I'M AT HOME.
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
WE'RE MAKING
OUR CAJUN SEASONING.
SEA SALT,
CAYENNE PEPPER,
THYME, WHITE PEPPER,
OREGANO,
GRANULATED GARLIC,
GRANULATED ONION,
BLACK PEPPER.
AND A TON PAPRIKA.
OKAY, MIX IT
ALL TOGETHER.
AND THIS WILL GET ADDED
INTO THE RED BEANS & RICE
IN THE COOKER?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT, SO THIS IS DONE.
WHAT'S NEXT?
WE'RE GONNA PUT
THE HAM HOCKS IN THE WATER.
SO THE SMOKED HAM HOCKS--
AFTER YOU TAKE
THE BOTTOM OF THE SHOULDER,
IT GETS CUT IN TWO SPOTS.
THIS AREA--DON'T USE MY FAT ARM
AS AN EXAMPLE, THOUGH.
SO WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA TAKE THIS HOCK--
IT'S GOT TONS OF FLAVOR.
SO YOU GOT BONE. YOU GOT
A LOT OF CONNECTIVE TISSUE--
AND THIS WILL WORK AS THE BASIS
OF THE RED BEANS & RICE.
CORRECT?
CORRECT.
SO INTO THE WATER. HOW LONG
ARE WE GONNA LET THESE BOIL?
FOR FIVE HOURS.
WHEN THEY COME OUT, THEY'LL JUST
BE KIND OF FORK TENDER.
AND I ASSUME--NOW I JUST GOT
TO GET THIS STRAIGHT--
BUT THIS GUY'S GOT TO BE WORKING
FROM A DRIED BEAN.
YEP.
ALL RIGHTY,
LET'S GET HER GOING.
OIL IN OUR POT,
THE HOLY TRINITY...
ONIONS, GREEN BELL PEPPER,
AND CELERY...
GARLIC.
KIND OF LIKE
THE CAJUN MIREPOIX.
WE'RE GONNA ADD
THE SEA SALT,
THAT FABULOUS
CAJUN SEASONING WE MADE.
A WHOLE MESS
OF CHICKEN STOCK, BOSS.
WHOLE MESS
OF CHICKEN STOCK.
MAKE YOUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK?
MAKE OUR OWN
CHICKEN STOCK.
OUR RED BEANS,
AND BAY LEAVES.
AND WE'RE GONNA LET THESE
COOK DOWN FOR HOW LONG?
A MERE SIX HOURS.
MERE SIX HOURS. JUST LET THEM
SIT THERE AND SIMMER.
THEN AT THE END
OF THAT PROCESS,
THAT'S WHEN
WE'LL ADD IN THE...
HAM STOCK.
THE HAM STOCK COMING FROM
WHEN WE BOILED THE HAM HOCKS.
YES.
AND THEN WE'LL ADD IN
THE PICKED MEAT.
OOH.
YEP.
SO YOU TAKE IT SERIOUSLY.
YEAH, IT'S KIND OF
A LEGENDARY DISH
SO YOU GOT TO MAKE IT
THE CORRECT WAY.
LOVE IT.
WE READY TO GO?
WE'RE READY TO GO.
HIT IT.
YOU AND YOUR SCOOPY SCOOP.
PORTION CONTROL.
THERE YOU GO.
GET A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT HOCK.
AND SCALLIONS.
OF COURSE.
AND A HOMEMADE
CORN MUFFIN.
(as Bill) IT'S A HOMEMADE
CORN MUFFIN, HE SAID.
(normal voice) MMM.
NICE HEALTHY PORTION
OF THAT HOCK,
THE BEANS
ARE NICE AND TENDER.
SEE, I THINK RED BEANS & RICE
JUST DOESN'T GET THE RESPECT
THAT IT DESERVES.
YOU'VE GOT
THIS REALLY RICH FLAVOR.
A LITTLE HOMEMADE MUFFIN
YOU MAKE YOURSELF,
PILE THAT UP.
SWEET OF THE MUFFIN,
SALTINESS, RICHNESS, CREAMINESS
ALL TIED TOGETHER,
THAT'S WHY THAT MEAL IS A STAPLE
IN CREOLE AND CAJUN COOKING.
I GET DOWN WITH THAT,
MY BROTHER.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU.
(woman)
RED BEANS & RICE.
IT'S VERY GOOD. YOU CAN TASTE
THE HAM HOCK IN THERE.
IT DEFINITELY TASTES LIKE
IT'S BEEN COOKED ALL DAY.
THE BEANS ARE NICE AND TENDER.
THE RICE IS PERFECTLY COOKED.
IT'S VERY GOOD.
NOT TOO SALTY, IT'S VERY GOOD.
MM-HMM. MM-HMM.
AND YOU THINK THAT
I JUST WAS THE ONE SAYING IT.
(man) BBQ SPAGHETTI DINNER
IN THE WINDOW.
YOU COME HERE, AND YOU'RE HOME.
YOU'RE HAPPY. NOTHING BETTER.
IT DOES FEEL LIKE
A GOOD HIGHWAY 61 JOINT, MAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT I ALWAYS SAY,
GO '80s. (laughs)
(laughs)
UP NEXT...
LET'S GO.
WE'RE HEADED TO DOWNTOWN
SYRACUSE, NEW YORK...
NO DOUBLE-DIPPING.
(mumbles) OF COURSE,
I WOULDN'T DOUBLE--OH, LOOK.
FOR A RIGHTEOUS TASTE...
JUST GOOD OLD
SUGAR WATER.
OF LEBANESE COMFORT FOOD.
MMM.
YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THEORIES
ON TRIPLE "D"
IS GO TO COLLEGE TOWNS.
STUDENTS--THEY KNOW
WHERE TO FIND GREAT FOOD.
SO I'M HERE
IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK,
HOME OF S.U.,
SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY,
TO CHECK OUT THE MEDITERRANEAN
MENU AT BYBLOS.
HEY, GUYS.
EVERYBODY COMES DOWN HERE
FOR THEIR MIDDLE EASTERN FOOD.
SO TELL ME,
WHAT MAKES THE FOOD SO GREAT?
YOU JUST--
YOU FEEL THE LOVE.
DO YOU FEEL IT? I FELT IT.
AND IT WAS FADY KHABBAZ'S LOVE
OF HIS MOM'S LEBANESE RECIPES
THAT HAD HIM OPENING THIS PLACE
IN 2009.
YOU FOUND
THE LOCATION?
YEAH, WE WERE LOOKING
FOR A WHILE.
I JUST REMEMBER
ALWAYS THINKING
WE GOT TO GET
IN THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS.
SHE HAD A PASSION
FOR IT,
AND SHE CAN SERVE UP
SOME GOOD EATS.
HE AIN'T KIDDING.
VIOLETTE KHABBAZ SPECIALIZES
IN ALL MIDDLE EASTERN CLASSICS,
FROM STUFFED GRAPE LEAVES...
NO DOUBLE-DIPPING.
(mumbles) OF COURSE,
I WOULDN'T DOUBLE--OH, LOOK.
(laughs)
TO SPANAKOPITA
TO WHAT ELSE? FALAFEL.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY KNOWN
FOR PHIL'S FALAFELS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS RECIPE VIOLETTE GOT
FROM HER HUSBAND PHIL.
HE'S THE FALAFEL KING.
(Guy) HE'S
THE FALAFEL KING?
PHIL'S FALAFEL.
YEAH, SURE.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA
MAKE FALAFEL WRAP.
FALAFEL WRAP.
YES.
VERY NICE.
TAKE ME TO THE PROMISED LAND.
TAKE THE FAVA BEANS
AND THE CHICKPEAS.
PUT IT IN THE BLENDER.
SOME GARLIC,
SOME ONION.
SOME ONIONS.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE THIS
INTO A PASTE.
RIGHT.
THAT'S IT?
NO, WE HAVE
TO MOVE IT AROUND.
WE'RE JUST GONNA DO THIS
THE WHOLE TIME? (whistles)
THE WHOLE TIME.
NEXT, KIDS, WE'RE GONNA
WATCH PAINT DRY.
AND THAT'S THE KIND OF TEXTURE
WE'RE LOOKING FOR?
YES.
NOW WE CAN ADD
ALL THE SPICES--
ALLSPICE, CINNAMON,
CUMIN,
CORIANDER, BLACK PEPPER,
SALT, CRUSHED RED PEPPER...
(whistles)
CAVALCADE OF SPICES.
CAYENNE PEPPER,
AND HOT CURRY, TOO.
YOU LIVE ON THE EDGE. THIS IS
GONNA BE A SPICY FALAFEL?
IT IS SPICY.
NOW I MIX IT ALL UP.
THIS IS GONNA SET OVERNIGHT
AND, UH...
MARRY THE FLAVORS.
YES. FOR 24 HOURS.
NOW IT'S READY.
WHOO.
(laughs)
WHOO! THAT'LL WAKE YOU UP.
OKAY, LET'S SEE IT.
WE ADD BAKING SODA.
MIX IT ALL TOGETHER.
AND THEN WE'LL FORM IT
IN THE BALL.
AH. OOH.
RIGHT.
OOH. I HAVEN'T SEEN
THIS ONE.
WHAT'S THAT OVER THERE?
THAT'S FOR SHAWARMA.
MM.
WHERE DID THE THING GO?
WHAT HAPPENED TO IT?
(man laughs)
OH, IT'S MAGIC...
DISAPPEARED.
YOU WANT TO USE MINE?
YES, I WILL.
I GRABBED MINE
FROM HOME.
SO THE MOLD HELPS IT
KIND OF COMPACT IT TOGETHER...
RIGHT.
UNIFORM SIZE.
SO THIS IS GONNA FRY UP.
YES.
AND YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO STAND 'EM UP LIKE THAT?
YES, TO DRY.
NOW WE HAVE THE PITA.
OKAY, WE'LL PUT
FIRST PARSLEY,
RADISHES...
TOMATOES.
TAHINI SAUCE MADE OF
SESAME AND LEMON, AND WATER.
FALAFEL.
TOP IT
WITH MORE TAHINI SAUCE.
WRAP IT.
NOW WE'LL CUT IT
IN HALF.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM. IT'S DELICIOUS.
THE FALAFEL ITSELF
IS REALLY GOOD.
IT'S PROBABLY THE MOST SEASONED
FALAFEL I'VE HAD.
MMM.
IT'S A GREAT MIX.
YOU'VE GOT A NICE BALANCE
ALL THE WAY THROUGH IT.
YOU'VE GOT YOURSELF
A VEGAN SANDWICH
THAT HAS THE RICHNESS
AND THE COMPLEXITIES
OF WHAT PEOPLE TYPICALLY GET IN
A MEAT SANDWICH OR IN A BURRITO.
ABSOLUTELY.
EXCELLENT.
VERY NICE.
(woman) HERE'S
YOUR FALAFEL WRAP.
(man) IT'S GOT TO BE CRISPY
ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT YOU KNOW, A LITTLE MUSHY
ON THE INSIDE.
AND THIS IS THE BEST FALAFEL
I'VE EVER HAD
OUTSIDE OF MIDDLE EAST
ITSELF.
I LOVE IT BECAUSE
THE INGREDIENTS ARE SO FRESH.
IT HAS, LIKE, ALMOST, LIKE,
A LITTLE BITE TO IT.
GYRO PLATE'S UP.
THEY SAY YOU CAN TASTE
WHEN SOMEBODY'S PASSIONATE
ABOUT SOMETHING,
AND IT'S DEFINITELY SOMETHING
THAT VIOLETTE
HOLDS CLOSE TO HER HEART.
SO YOU'RE THE BOSS.
RIGHT.
YES, I KNOW
WHO THE BOSS IS.
'CAUSE AFTER COOKING FOR
HER WHOLE FAMILY GROWING UP...
CHICKEN KABOB ALMOST READY.
SHE'S USED
TO RUNNING THE KITCHEN.
PEOPLE ALWAYS ASK ME
WHAT I LIKE ON THE MENU.
I SAY EVERYTHING.
AND THE REST OF THE MENU
ARE HER RECIPES.
(man) WELL, THE FOOD
IS PHENOMENAL,
AND FOR THE GYRO--
THOSE ARE ACTUALLY MY FAVORITE.
THE TABBOULEH IS ABSOLUTELY
AMAZING. I LOVE IT.
YOUR WALNUT BAKLAVA.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
(imitates explosion)
THE BOSS IS HOOKING ME UP
WITH THE SWEETER SIDE
OF SYRACUSE.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE WALNUT BRITTLE
IN THE MIDDLE. MMM.
(Guy) WELCOME BACK
TO BYBLOS IN SYRACUSE.
I'M HANGING OUT
WITH THE SUPER VIOLETTE.
THE QUEEN OF LEBANESE COOKING
IN UPSTATE NEW YORK.
AND NOW
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE BAKLAVA
WITH WALNUTS.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
SO WE GOT CRUSHED WALNUTS.
CINNAMON, AND NOW WE ADD
SOME SUGAR TO IT.
THEN WE MIX THEM
ALL TOGETHER.
THEN WE GET
THE PHYLLO DOUGH.
WHO WAS MAKING DOUGH THAT THIN
100 YEARS AGO?
WHOA.
NOW WE HAVE
TO ADD THE BUTTER.
THEN WE PUT
THE PHYLLO DOUGH DOWN.
I PUT, LIKE,
TWO, THREE PIECES IN.
VERY NICE.
THEN I BUTTER IT, TOO.
THEN WE PUT MORE
ON THE TOP.
NOW WE'LL ADD
THE WALNUTS.
WHOA. THAT THICK?
YES.
THAT'S LIKE A DUMP TRUCK
OF WALNUTS.
HOW MANY MORE SHEETS
ON TOP?
LIKE, 15 SHEETS,
15, 16.
OH, CUT IT AHEAD OF TIME,
SO IT DOESN'T...
(imitates explosion)
EVERYWHERE.
THEN WE ADD
THE REST OF THE BUTTER.
AND NOBODY HAS ANY TYPE OF
A CHOLESTEROL ISSUE AROUND HERE.
♪ ROLL OUT THE BUTTER ♪
AND WHERE ARE WE GOING NOW?
IN THE OVEN.
IT COOKS FOR 30 MINUTES
FOR, LIKE, 400 DEGREES.
HERE WE GO.
NOW WE'RE READY TO ADD
THE SYRUP.
SO WE TAKE THE SUGAR.
ADD THE WATER.
AND WE'RE MAKING
A SIMPLE SYRUP.
RIGHT.
GOT IT.
THEN WE'LL LET IT BOIL
FOR, LIKE, FIVE MINUTES...
OKAY.
THEN ADD THE LEMON JUICE.
THEN LET IT BOIL
FOR 15 MORE MINUTES
TILL IT GETS THICK
LIKE HONEY.
NICE AND THICK,
LIKE A HONEY?
YES. LIKE A HONEY.
REALLY?
OH, IT GOES ON TOP.
ABSOLUTELY.
GOT IT.
JUST GOOD OLD SUGAR WATER.
(laughs)
NOW WE HAVE TO ADD
THE PISTACHIO.
OKAY, SERVE IT UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
MMM.
(laughs)
WOW!
DO YOU OWN A SUGAR PLANTATION?
NO.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE WALNUT BRITTLE
IN THE MIDDLE. MMM.
THIS IS THE MOST WALNUTS
AND THE MOST SUGAR
THAT I'VE EVER SEEN IN BAKLAVA
IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
I LIKE TO SEE THINGS DONE
IN EXTREMES. THIS IS EXTREME.
NICE JOB.
YOUR WALNUT BAKLAVA.
YOU GET A GREAT CRUNCH
WITH THE NUTS,
BUT THEN THE PHYLLO DOUGH KIND
OF JUST MELTS ON YOUR TONGUE.
I HAVE SUCH A SWEET TOOTH,
AND THIS IS SO PERFECTLY SWEET.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
DOWNTOWN SYRACUSE
IS ON ITS WAY BACK,
AND THE REASON WHY PEOPLE
ARE COMING BACK DOWNTOWN
ARE BECAUSE OF BYBLOS.
I CAN NEVER COME IN
JUST TO SAY HELLO.
IT'S ALWAYS, "ARE YOU HUNGRY?"
NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU.
MAKE SURE THAT YOU PAY ATTENTION
TO THE BOSS, RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
WE GOT PLENTY MORE JOINTS
TO FIND ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
WE'RE HERE
IN ST. LOUIS, MISS--
MISSOURI.
I WANTED TO SEE IF IT'S MISSOURI
OR "MISSOUR-A."
SEE, I SAY MISSOUR-A.
YOU DON'T HAVE "BROCCOL-A,"
DO YOU?
I DO HAVE A BROCCOL-A.
GIVE ME SOME BROCCOL-A.