Hey, everybody!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, it's already tasty.
...we're sounding the alarm...
[ Horn blares ]
...for dishes
with real-deal roots.
Dude.
This is out of bounds.
In Toronto, Canada...
[ Imitates
record scratching ]
...the Jewish deli...
[ Exhales deeply ]
This is what we do.
...perfecting
the smoked-meat sandwich...
Okay. I'll take fatty.
Not that I need it.
...and going old school
with the schmaltz.
That's as big
as my head.
Don't say anything.
Then, somewhere in
Orange County, California...
This is not gonna suck.
...this Singapore
food truck...
Crab cake.
A lot going on in there.
...slinging the savory flavors
of southeast Asia.
That's the last thing I expected
when I pulled up here.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You know when you go on vacation
and you leave your hometown?
You leave
all your comfort food behind.
I was in Italy and I was
jonesing for some Mexican food.
So, if you're a fan of delis,
and I'm talking about old-school
Jewish-style delis,
and you're cruising through
Toronto, Canada, don't worry.
They got a joint for you.
It's right here at Caplansky's.
It just smells amazing
when you walk in,
and it just hits you
and you want to eat.
You don't take little bites
at Caplansky's.
It's Jewish soul food.
FIERI:
Something owner Zane Caplansky
knows a lot about.
It's the food
that I grew up with.
that my parents
and my grandparents
grew up with.
And when he couldn't find
a smoked-meat sandwich
that hit his high standards,
he decided to do it himself.
[ Exhales deeply ]
This is what we do.
Hand-rubbed, house-smoked,
hand-sliced.
Best smoked meat
you'll ever have.
And he passed on the secrets
to his kitchen manager,
Patrick Berrigan.
What are we gonna
make first?
We're gonna make the spice rub
for the smoked meat first.
All right. So, first thing --
brown sugar.
Next thing, nutmeg.
Little coriander seed.
A whole bunch of it.
Oh, yeah.
Ground --
Chili?
Nope. Ground cloves.
Cloves. Whoa!
That much?
Yep.
Chili flakes.
Add some spice.
A little cinnamon.
Fennel seed.
So you toast all the spices
ahead of time.
Yes.
Great.
And then we do
some cracked black pepper.
Brown mustard seed.
I'd like 10,000 marbles,
please.
Some celery seed.
Dried onion?
Yes.
Never seen it that big.
Garlic flakes.
Dill seed.
And the best
hickory-smoked salt.
Love it.
What's up next is
we get our brisket out
and give her a good rub.
You don't brine it
before you rub it?
No.
Oh, this is interesting.
2 1/2 gallons of water.
Yep.
And then a liter
of curing salt.
A liter of it?
A liter.
It's a little sweet.
Yeah, it's nice, huh?
Yeah, eh?
Yeah, just throw it in.
Mix it up real good.
And what's
this funky runky?
Ascorbic acid.
It helps, like,
kind of preserve the brisket.
Ooh.
Put a lid on it and then
throw it in the fridge
for about a week
to a week and a half.
Rinse it off, rub it again,
then go to the smoker.
Yeah.
Word.
How long's
this brisket been in?
For about
12 1/2 hours now.
Nice.
Yep. She looks good.
Now, there's really a way
that this is cut.
The cutters up front
really have a technique
that make it
that much more delectable?
Oh, my God, yes.
And you got a guy up there
that'll show me?
Oh, he's amazing.
He's an artist.
So, this is our slicer,
Naomichi.
The tallest slicer
I've ever seen.
What choices do I have?
I recommend
the fatty parts.
The fatty parts?
Okay, I'll take fatty.
Not that I need it.
He's faster
than my vertical slicer.
So, this is the fatty?
Yep.
Look at that.
Hit me with the mustard.
Whatever you think.
That's what we're
talking about.
Oh, my God.
Tender, little bit of spice,
good amount of smoke, juicy.
Mmm.
That's awesome, buddy.
From the rub to the brine
to the smoke to the slice,
you knock out
every factor of it.
MAN: It's phenomenal.
One of the best smoked-meat
sandwiches I've ever had.
CAPLANSKY: Everything we do
here, we do it from scratch.
If we don't do it ourselves,
we get it from other people
that are family-owned,
small-batch, old-school.
Start to finish,
this is what we do.
FIERI:
It's an attention to detail
that starts with the basics.
We use schmaltz
as much as we can.
Schmaltz. Chicken fat.
You've got to love it.
As olive oil
is to Italian food,
pork fat is
to southern cooking,
schmaltz is
to Jewish food.
And it's the first ingredient
in what I've dubbed
the King Kong of knish.
Smoked-meat knish.
The knish.
It's really good comfort food.
It's just like my Bubbeh
used to make.
Just good stuff.
Time to schmaltz.
Time to schmaltz
right now.
All right,
crank up the heat, kid.
First thing we're gonna put
in here is the chicken fat.
That is about the most pure,
golden, virgin chicken fat
that I've ever seen.
Well, thank you.
Next thing we add
is sliced white onions.
Just a little bit
of salt.
And the chicken skin.
Yeah.
Okay.
We have to render it for about
half an hour to 45 minutes.
Whoa.
So, now we got our schmaltz.
Now we make the knish.
Yukon gold potatoes.
That have been cooked
all the way down?
Yep.
Cooked all the way down.
And lean smoked meat,
ground up.
Hurry up
before I eat it all.
And a bit of schmaltz.
Did you just sclop that out
of your hand?
Sure did.
Some rosemary
and some ground coriander.
Form it into a ball.
That's one?
Yep.
Is this a normal size
for a knish?
Welcome to Caplansky's.
Place it in the middle
of the puff pastry.
This is like
knish gone wild.
[ Laughs ]
And then egg wash.
Make sure she sticks.
Another egg wash on top.
Sesame seeds to garnish.
That's enormous.
All right, in the oven.
What temp?
350 for about 35 minutes.
Voilà.
That's as big
as my head.
Don't say anything.
For some reason, I thought
we were gonna hear a chain saw
when you got that
fired up.
We throw some gravy
on the plate.
It's a meal in itself.
There you go.
Dude, look at the size
of this thing.
Dude.
This is out of bounds.
[ Laughs ]
It's salty, it's rich,
it's smoked, it's schmaltzy.
The flavors are great,
the balance is awesome,
the portion's ridiculous.
This will change
the way you think of knish.
Knish is up.
Not that I need
anything else to eat,
but if we were gonna have
something else,
what would it be?
Let's have a little desert,
you know.
Some maple bacon
doughnuts.
Maple bacon doughnuts.
All right. I think I can be
talked into that.
Not bad.
FIERI: We're hanging out
at Caplansky's deli
in Toronto, Canada,
where owner Zane Caplansky
has built a shrine
to smoked meat.
He's putting it in everything,
and I do mean everything.
Save room for some
maple bacon doughnuts?
MAN: Absolutely.
Maple bacon doughnuts,
ready to go.
All right. We're making
the dough for the doughnuts?
Yep. So, baking soda.
Baking powder.
Whole lot of sugar.
Some buttermilk. Eggs.
Salt?
Yep. Little bit of salt.
Nutmeg.
Egg yolks.
[ Imitates
record scratching ]
See him start popping
over there?
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
Beautiful.
Throw in
a bit of the flour.
Cake flower?
Just regular A.P. flour.
Some crankage on this?
Yep.
Slowly.
Hold it. Hold it.
We keep that going
for about 25 minutes.
And then we have to
let it sit overnight, too.
All right, now we're gonna
cure the beef bacon.
The beef bacon?
Yep.
Oh, 'cause there's no pork
in this joint.
No pork.
No pork?
After working here, pork bacon
doesn't even cut it anymore.
Let's hit it.
It's a 2 to 1 ratio
to curing salt
to brown sugar.
And then one tablespoon
of ascorbic acid.
And just give her a mix.
Make sure
it's all covered.
So, we're using
the belly of the beef.
Yep. Exactly.
It gets cured for about a week
to a week and a half,
and then it gets smoked
for about 8 1/2 hours.
Out of the depths of the smoker
comes beef bacon.
All right, give me a slab of
this. I want to check this out.
That's
pretty crazy, dude.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Not too smoky,
but rich, chewy, salty.
Wow.
Now time to do
the doughnuts.
All right, it's a little bit
of flour down.
Just roll it up
into a little ball.
Throw some beef bacon
in there.
Fold it up.
Yep.
Roll it a little more.
Then we'll throw them
in the deep fryer.
You gonna serve that
with gravy?
No. Maple syrup.
We're gonna remind
all the viewers at home
that this is a doughnut
stuffed with beef bacon.
Now drizzled
with maple syrup
and a little
powdered sugar.
There you go.
Oh, it's already tasty.
Mmm.
That maple syrup, with that
little bit of saltiness there
of the beef bacon.
Wasn't what I was
expecting.
I've had doughnuts with bacon
on the outside of them
quite a few places.
But that right there,
that's something in itself.
Great job, Pat.
They're amazing.
What makes them amazing?
The nice mixture
of maple syrup and bacon
with the sweet dough.
Oh, my goodness.
That's the future of "Triple D"
right there, by the way.
Hey, Zane,
awesome joint, man.
Nice people,
funny place, good energy.
Appreciate it.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
to Orange County, California...
Andale.
...where a Singapore
food truck...
[ Whistles ]
...is serving up
some serious flavor.
There's a lot going on
in there.
You been here before?
GALVAN: Crab cake.
I hear it's the bomb.
It's a Singapore concept.
And they're never in the same
location for lunch or dinner.
They're from
Orange County, California.
This is Chomp Chomp Nation.
Yeah, it'll be me and
the millions of people with me.
All day.
Two steak, tofu, bean, and lamb.
Lots of fun, unique foods.
Singapore tofu burger,
please.
How do you describe to people
what Singaporean food is?
It's exotic,
tropical Chinese food.
FIERI: Brought to America
by the husband-and-wife team
of Robert Zuetell
and Gina Galvan.
We call it quick gourmet.
Quick gourmet.
Comes out in 3 minutes,
looks like $1 million.
Now, if you couldn't tell,
Robert's background
is in restaurant P.R.
And Gina, I mean,
she just traveled the world
as a food technologist.
I worked for all kinds
of restaurant chains
and food manufacturers.
To develop
food concepts and food recipes?
And she's picked up flavors
that are
turning the truck
into a spice market
with an outrageous blend
mixed into this top seller.
Crab cake.
A delicious lunch
for a good price.
[ Imitates drumbeats ]
[ Laughter ]
When I went to Singapore,
I figured out
this is
what Singapore tastes like.
And that's why I call this
the aromatics package.
So, the key ingredients --
ginger.
Ginger.
Lemongrass.
Shallots.
Galangal.
Galangal?
A relative of the ginger?
Yes.
Garlic.
Thai chilies.
And finally,
the kaffir lime leaf.
Now,
the kaffir lime leaf,
there's just such an intensity
and such a richness...
[ Sniffs ]
...and such an amazing
aromatic flavor and essence
that comes from it.
Okay.
Are you just gonna
make this into a paste?
Kind of a rough paste.
All right. There it be.
[ Whistles ]
Awesome.
So, what are we gonna
make with this?
We're gonna make
crab-cake sandwich.
Andale.
What is this?
This is rice cake.
Cook it
in this plastic,
and it compresses the rice
as it cooks.
You boil it in that
or does it come
pre-cooked in this?
No,
you boil it in this.
And in Singapore,
it's called ketupat.
It tastes like
you cooked a bunch of rice,
little overcooked,
and then compressed it.
Mm-hmm.
The reason I put this
in the crab cake is because
it makes the crab stand up
nice and firm, you know?
Crumble that up
a little bit.
Taste of Singapore
in the aromatics packet.
Sri Lankan
blue crab leg and claw.
Chili crab sauce.
I like that.
Sweet chili sauce.
Mayonnaise.
Panko bread crumbs.
Panko.
Egg.
Oh, yes.
This is looking good.
What is that
over there?
[ Laughs ]
Caught you.
Can you get me that, please,
which is the panko.
We're gonna make it
a little crispy on the outside.
That's a good-looking
crab cake.
Isn't that pretty?
Okay, now we're gonna
walk over to the fryer.
You deep-fry it?
Yep.
FIERI: Everything's cooked
in there, so you're just
frying it enough
to put a crisp on it.
Yep.
What are we gonna make?
Our lemongrass kaffir lime
vinaigrette.
Grape-seed oil.
Rice vinegar.
Our aromatics.
Kaffir lime leaves.
Kaffir lime leaf.
Whole thing.
And shallots.
Country Dijon mustard.
An emulsifier.
You're
pretty smart there.
Chinese white pepper.
Lychee juice.
Lychee juice?
It's tropical
and exotic,
so I like that exotic flavor
in my vinaigrette.
Sweet chili sauce.
And cilantro.
Oh, yeah.
Yes.
Mmm.
Here we go.
Now we're making the slaw.
The slaw.
So, we have
green cabbage
and red cabbage.
Carrots. Here we go.
Daikon.
Ooh, I like the daikon.
Cucumber.
Mango.
Oh, mango?
Uh-huh.
Red onion.
And this is the one I want
to know what it really is.
Onion?
Green apple.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
All right, so, we mix it up,
and then we'll serve
the slaw dressing on it
to order?
Yes.
Now we're gonna
plate up our crab cake.
Our tiger slaw.
Our
lemongrass vinaigrette.
Our crab cake.
Spicy ketchup.
Chili crab sauce.
Mm-hmm.
And the slaw.
This is not gonna suck.
I'm telling you what.
That's tasty.
You've got
tangy, sweet, crunchy, salty.
This really nice balance.
And the kicker
to the whole thing
is that slaw.
Yay.
That's ridiculous.
[ Laughs ]
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Wow.
Crab cake.
MAN: This thing tastes like
a really expensive crab cake.
It's delicious.
The crab cake, please.
Awesome.
FIERI:
And there's more deliciousness
where that came from,
like a juicy burger
packed with mint and spices.
I'll give you a hint.
Baa.
[ Chuckles ]
We'll work on that.
When we come back.
FIERI: We're in
Orange County, California,
where a husband-and-wife team
is bringing
Singaporean flavor
to the people.
GALVAN:
I like to see people smile.
I like to see the,
"Wow, this is great."
FIERI: The only challenge is
pinning down
this 9-ton
tiger-striped behemoth.
MAN: Find out wherever they are
and have the best
gourmet lunch truck around.
FIERI: So, they make it easy
with a combo
of new-school social media
and old-school technique
picked up from
the ice-cream man.
[ Horn blares tune ]
That's
the Chomp Chomp growl.
You hit that horn
and you pull up to
an apartment complex.
People
don't have to cook.
They can come out
and get great, fresh
Singaporean food.
Yes.
FIERI:
Like this gourmet sandwich...
GALVAN: Lamb burger.
...inspired by the Little India
section of Singapore.
Delicious.
Lamb's big in Singapore?
It is.
So, we have Halal lamb.
Halal lamb?
Halal.
Really?
Yes.
The humane treating
and slaughtering of the animal.
First up
is the aromatics package.
Again, the magic mix.
We have mint.
Parsley.
You have
some cilantro in there?
Cilantro.
Dark soy sauce.
Okay.
Very Singaporean.
We've got
some Worcester.
And
tamarind concentrate.
Really?
Yeah.
So, you got
a sweet and a tang.
Uh-huh.
And then our spice.
Mild curry powder.
Mild curry.
And hot curry.
Yeah.
Chinese white pepper
and kosher salt.
[ Whistles ]
Okay. I've got to
stand on my tippy toes.
You're gonna fall in.
[ Chuckling ] I know.
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
You can do it. Work harder.
Focus on your future.
Dig deep.
Meld the flavors.
It's ready to go.
[ Normal voice ]
It's ready to go?
All right.
So, we make the patty.
How many ounces?
We're doing four.
Then we flat-top this?
Flat-top it.
Grill it up on both sides.
Mm-hmm.
And make some yogurt sauce.
Uh-huh.
First ingredient
is Greek yogurt.
Got it.
Then we've got
parsley.
Cilantro.
Mint.
Lime juice --
freshly squeezed.
And our curry powder.
Again.
Mild and hot.
Mild and the hot.
And lastly,
a little bit of kosher salt.
Give this a stir.
Mmm. Smells good.
Can I taste it?
Yes.
Wow.
There's a lot going on
in there.
Our cooked lamb's done.
Nice.
Just
a little bit of sauce.
Yogurt sauce.
Correct.
And edamame sprouts.
There we go.
That's
the last thing I expected
when I pulled up here.
[ Laughs ]
I think Singapore,
I think soy sauce,
Asian food.
But I'm a sucker
for a lamb burger.
The flavors
are well balanced.
I like
the spicy curry.
And the lamb, the herbs.
And then the bean sprouts,
I think,
are a different texture.
I love that crunch,
the sweetness,
herbaceousness of them.
The whole thing's
a package deal.
I mean,
it is a great lamb burger.
You're the bomb dot-com.
Chomp Chomp Nation.
[ Chuckles ]
Really unique flavors.
WOMAN: Really melts
in your mouth. Really tender.
Lots of great spice.
FIERI:
Congratulations.
Awesome place.
Thank you.
Funky joint, and you really
take a lot of appreciation,
a lot of time, lot of care,
lot of energy in your food.
Awesome.
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We got
plenty more joints to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
What do you feel
the economy in Toronto
is looking forward to
in the next upcoming year?
Mm.
Lower prices
and the oil's going up.
[ Laughter ]
Shut the front door.