Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hey, kids.
...the Camaro's racing...
This is just everybody
playing together.
...from land to sea...
How do we start this?
...in Olympia, Washington.
[ As Groucho Marx ] Well, I'll
tell you something, sweetheart.
The Brew Pub pairing suds
with housemade specialties.
Holy cannoli.
In Kitty Hawk, North Carolina,
the seaside tradition...
100,000 people a summer.
...reeling in tourists
and locals alike.
When it's good,
the locals know.
And in Syracuse, New York,
the underground joint...
Magical.
...serving up homemade twists...
Do you sleep upside down
in a dark cave?
...on tradition.
Who came up
with this crazy idea?
Me.
This is whacked.
That's all right here, right now
on "Triple D."
You remember the beer Olympia?
Oly?
They had that tag line,
"It's the water."
Well, I'm in that town --
Olympia, Washington.
So, when you show up
to a town like this,
what are you looking for?
A great brewpub.
But not just a great brewpub,
one that has great food.
The place I'm told to check out
is right here at Fish Tale.
Here you are, Todd.
Thank you.
WOMAN: As far as
variety and selection,
it's really
the best place to go.
FIERI: It's been Olympia's go-to
spot for craft beer since 1993.
How many different types of beer
do you guys make?
SHELL: We're making about 20
on average.
And then we do seasonals and
special one-offs all the time.
And to pair with Brewmaster
Brad Shell's high-end suds,
Pub Manager Max DeJarnatt
knows the food's got to be
off the hook, too.
We're brewing craft beer,
so we want to have craft food.
And people here,
they want to eat some good food.
If you're gonna drink
that kind of beer,
you should have
that kind of food.
Exactly.
FIERI: So, Chef Kerin Lewis...
Crab cannelloni.
...is going local...
We really feel like it's
a good flavor of the Northwest.
FIERI: ...with fish and chips
made from Alaskan cod,
and Northwest russet potatoes,
to a clam steamer
sourced from nearby Hood Canal,
or a crab cannelloni
stuffed with Alaskan Bay shrimp
and Dungeness crab
straight out of the Puget Sound.
Crab cannelloni.
It's just delicious.
How do we start this?
First of all,
I puree my bay shrimp.
I don't know about this.
It's like
shrimp cotton candy.
Yeah.
Hey, kids.
So, now we take
the shrimp cotton candy,
and what are we gonna do
with it?
Shrimp "Ice, Ice, Baby?"
We go with
the Dungeness crab.
That, I like.
Lemon zest, then we have nutmeg,
some parsley.
Okay.
A little egg yolk.
Egg yolk.
Sauteed shallots.
How do you spell "cannelloni,"
by the way?
C-a-n-n-e-l-l-o--
E-g-g-r-o-l-l?
Yeah, egg roll.
This is what you're gonna use
for your pasta? Nice.
When I started making it,
I used pasta sheets.
And they were too thick
for this texture.
This is a thin texture.
But when you get some of those
pasta sheets and they swell up,
they're kind of like
the thickness of a lasagna.
Right.
So,
what's gonna happen now?
Ricotta cheese
and parmesan.
Excellent.
Some gloves?
Some gloves.
I play with my food.
You play with your food?
Mm-hmm.
You want to break up
the crab,
but you want to leave it
so you can still tell it's --
You want to have some texture
of the crab.
Some texture.
You want me to bust out
any of these sheets?
Sure,
I need three of them.
Chop, chop.
So, here's the thing
when it comes to these skins.
Make sure
that you keep them cool,
and make sure that you keep them
from drying out,
'cause they are pastas.
Whoa!
Holy cannoli.
Yeah, that, too.
You got this down
to a science, girl.
[ As Groucho Marx ] Well, I'll
tell you something, sweetheart.
[ Normal voice ] Okay?
Okay.
Then we'll cut them in half?
Mm-hmm.
That's good.
I was scared.
And now I'm gonna make
the roasted red pepper sauce
for the cannelloni.
Garlic butter
and heavy cream.
And then we have
the roasted red peppers.
FIERI: So, the roasted
red peppers are pureed?
Mm-hmm.
Once it gets really hot,
I add the parmesan
a little at a time
until it gets thick.
So, basically,
this is an alfredo
with roasted red pepper sauce.
Very nice. And that's gonna go
over the top.
Nice. Nice.
So, it goes in the oven
for how long?
About eight minutes.
Awesome.
All right, so,
now what do you do to it?
I'm gonna go ahead
and garnish it
with a little bit
of parmesan cheese,
'cause you can never
get enough of that.
And a little green,
'cause you need your vegetables.
When you come
to the great Northwest
and you hear all this talk
of the seafood,
you expect
that you're gonna find places
that are doing, like, real-deal,
super seafood dishes.
That's seafood.
I mean, you got tons of shrimp
in there, tons of crab.
There's a little bit of cheese
to bind that,
but the ratio
of seafood to cheese --
I think it's about
three to one.
And that really
is delicious.
Great dish. Nice job.
FIERI: So, I had the surf.
And when we come back to
Fish Tale Brew Pub in Olympia...
Now the fun begins.
...I'm going in for the turf.
FIERI: "Triple D's" hanging
at the Fish Tale Brew Pub
in Olympia, Washington...
Fish tacos.
...where they're combining
award-winning beers
with righteous
down-home cooking...
Here's your lobster po'boy.
...all served up
in an atmosphere I'd call homey.
Everybody is kind of at home
here --
People from government offices
to college kids.
FIERI: But there's one thing
from home you won't find here.
We don't have any TVs,
so there's always
good conversation.
Who do you guys talk to?
Each other.
FIERI: Great conversation,
house-brewed beer,
and a killer meal
like this pub grub classic.
Bangers and mash.
Kerin's cranking out
from scratch.
Let's make bangers.
LEWIS: Okay.
We're gonna grind some pig.
You say it
with such enthusiasm.
We're gonna one time?
Two times?
Just one time.
This is the kind of grind
we're going to --
this nice, coarse grind?
Yep, that's what we want.
Then we'll mix it
with the seasoning and stuff it?
Right.
Hit it.
We're gonna add
the bread crumbs,
which is a mix
of sourdough and marble rye.
Ooh.
Nutmeg, mace.
Mace is the outer skin
of the nutmeg.
Fresh sage, fresh marjoram,
and fresh thyme.
Thyme's one of
my all-time favorites.
Yeah, I love thyme.
Pepper, paprika,
lemon zest, salt.
Then I've got eggs.
A little bit of water.
You'd like to put that extra
moisture in there if you can.
Now the fun begins.
Doctor, doctor?
Doctor, doctor.
So, thoroughly mix
all of this.
You want to get it
so that it's so combined
that it looks like
one piece of meat.
Can we have
some meat-mixing music?
Hit it!
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
Oh, you're really
getting into it now.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, so,
we got that mixed enough.
Now, we're gonna take it --
We've got some soaked casings
over there.
Yes, some hog casings.
Okay.
All right, here we go.
We're gonna pack the meat
into the hopper.
Okay.
Put the casing on.
And it's good to have water
on the sheet pan.
So it doesn't stick?
Yeah.
I can hear it. Come on.
There we go. We got it.
You want me
to do the cranking?
Sure.
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
It's like a workout
in the kitchen.
[ Normal voice ] Okay, so,
what's gonna happen now?
I'm gonna tie it off.
Okay, so, you twist,
measure that one off.
What exactly is going on
at this juncture?
This is called
a traditional butcher's tie.
Huh.
Okay, so, the idea is that
everybody's linked together
so when you got and hang it
in the smokehouse,
you would hang it
by this combined group
so everybody's supporting
each other.
That's right.
Dig it.
So, we'll let this cure
for 24 hours?
24 hours, and then we'll
blanch it in our beer.
What kind of beer is that?
It's organic I.P.A.
Okay. Next?
We're gonna make the rue
for the gravy.
A little bit of olive oil.
This is a flour that's got salt,
pepper, paprika,
and we use it
for our beer batter.
Okay.
And the beef stock
is made in-house.
Roast the bones,
the whole giddyup?
The whole giddyup.
I like it.
And now a little beer.
Which beer is this?
This is Hefeweizen.
Hefeweizen.
And how long do the sausages
take back there?
It takes eight minutes
to cook there,
and then we put them on the
grill for about five minutes.
Give a nice, little crust
to them.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, and that's my gravy.
Okay, well,
we're dishing up.
We have our bangers marked
and the gravy we made.
And a little fresh parsley.
That's my bangers and mash.
Mmm.
Very floral.
I like that lemon
that comes through.
A little nutmeg
on the backside of it.
Nutmeg's the key.
This is a really nice
consistency of the meat.
Mmm. Good-tasting.
You definitely get a lot
of that beer coming through
and then a little grill to it so
it's not just a boiled sausage.
And the gravy, come on.
Check that out.
Impressed.
Nice job. Delicious.
Thank you.
She gave me knuckles.
It's fresh,
and it's prepared right.
It gives me everything I need.
Food's fantastic,
the service is great,
and we made a lot of our friends
down here.
We're here all the time,
and we really enjoy it.
Nice, guys. Thank you.
Congratulations.
FIERI: Up next...
Spank it.
...we're headed to Kitty Hawk,
North Carolina...
Chug, chug, chug.
...where
a summertime institution...
What do you know about risotto,
son?
...is serving up the sea.
Ah, one of the things I love
about "Triple D" --
it takes me to big cities,
it takes me to small towns,
it takes me
to historical landmarks.
This is Kitty Hawk,
North Carolina.
You know, Kitty Hawk,
the Wright brothers?
This is where aviation started.
I mean, it's incredible.
You know what else
is incredible?
100 years later,
this restaurant is serving
over 100,000 people a summer.
This is the Black Pelican.
Shrimp grit.
It's my favorite place
on the beach.
It's got just about what
everybody would want
in a place down here.
Hey, y'all. Here you go.
It's real-deal food?
Absolutely.
Fresh, always tasty,
chef's very creative.
FIERI:
That's Chef Jason Smith...
Shrimp app up.
...who,
like the Wright brothers,
has a bit of history here.
Well, I started out here when
I was 16, doing the steam bar.
You got veg
for the pork shank?
After years of honing
his craft elsewhere...
Table 10 up.
...he came back
to the place locals love.
It's got a little bit
of everything.
Cowboy burger up.
Whatever you want,
they've got it.
What is it,
everybody says,
"Oh, you go to Black Pelican,
you got to have the..."?
Citrus rosemary
brine chicken.
I like the combination
of flavors
with the citrus background.
And whatever the glaze is
is excellent.
All right, so, we start with
our airline chicken breast
into our brining pan.
Garlic.
Fresh garlic.
A whole rosemary stem's
in there.
Peppercorn.
Kosher salt.
A bunch of it.
And then we have just
granulated sugar -- white sugar.
Okay.
We got an orange.
We're gonna throw
the whole orange in there,
but we're gonna go ahead
and squeeze some juice in, also,
just to make sure --
Oh, thank you, sir.
Limes.
Water.
Okay, now,
how long is this gonna brine?
Usually,
about 24 hours is nice.
Chug, chug.
[ Chuckling ] Yeah.
I like to do
the skin side down.
That's really the main side
we're gonna mark just for
presentation purposes.
Pour some chicken stock on it.
Homemade chicken stock?
That's right.
Of course it is.
Put it in the convection oven
at 500 degrees.
So, we're gonna get our
smoked-gouda mashed potatoes.
Oh, I love smoked gouda!
Good.
Demi-glace?
Demi-glace.
Do that around the bowl.
This is not what I expected
to find in a seafood restaurant.
Well, you have to serve
chicken, too.
There's always
some chicken-eater.
Chicken-eater.
There's our chicken breast.
See, we got the grill marks
nice and caramelized.
And then we top it
with our sauté of baby spinach,
mushrooms, oven-roasted
tomatoes, and feta cheese.
That's the citrus
rosemary chicken.
Mmm.
Look at how juicy
that chicken is.
We don't want anybody
to take, you know, first seat
in the orchestra on this.
I mean, this is just everybody
playing together.
Spinach, mushroom, tomatoes,
the demi-glace,
the smoked-gouda
mashed potatoes,
and the citrus brine chicken.
Had the Wright brothers
had some of this,
they would have said,
"Guess what. We flew.
"Oh, and you got to try
the citrus brine chicken
over at the Black Pelican."
Citrus chicken up.
Nothing is overstated on it.
It's very delicate.
It's a very nice blend
of the seasoning and the sauce.
There's something good
going one here.
It's my home away from home.
[ Laughs ]
There's a lot of the same people
here,
and I think the visitors
like that, too.
I would think that the locals
would steer so far away
from the tourist area.
No, listen.
When it's good, the locals know.
FIERI: And one thing locals here
know about -- you got it.
Seafood.
Man: They use shrimp from here.
They use scallops.
Everything from here
is from here.
And when it's combined
with an Italian favorite,
you've got
a Black Pelican classic.
Wanchese fisherman's risotto
up.
What do you know about risotto,
son?
I know quite a bit
about risotto.
Okay,
give me the beginning.
So, we're gonna sweat
the onions.
Now we go with
the beautiful Arborio rice.
All right, I need to cut
this rascal open.
Watch out.
This work?
Yeah, that's a fish knife,
but we'll cut a bag with it.
Yeah.
All right, so,
we'll pour in the Arborio.
we'll toast this all down.
Get some garlic in there.
We'll start hitting it
with the chicken stock.
What's this?
Sweet corn. We put that in
just before we cool it.
Gives it nice color
and sweetness.
Spank it. Spank it.
Throw it on some sheet trays
to cool it down.
That's right.
So, the risotto's done,
pan's hot.
Take me to the...
Wanchese fisherman's
risotto.
We're gonna start out
with chopped bacon,
sea scallops, shrimp.
[ Fieri whistles ]
The reason we call it
Wanchese risotto
is because these scallops
come in from Port Wanchese.
The port of Wanchese?
Yeah.
Let them build
a little crust.
Yeah.
What else is gonna go
in the dish?
So, we're gonna go with
tomatoes, spinach, lump crab.
Put the risotto in the pan
now.
And then we're gonna add our
chicken stock and let it simmer.
All right, butter and cheese.
That's it.
A little bit of a pat.
Parmesan.
And that will just finish
creaming it up real good.
FIERI: Nice.
We top it with
our crispy sweet potato curls.
That's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
Mmm.
The risotto
is nice and tender.
The fresh spinach in there,
the lump crab, the bacon,
a little bit of butter,
the shrimp, the scallops.
I did not expect
this level of food
at a place that's doing
100,000 people in the summer.
Dynamite.
The combination of flavors
is wonderful.
They really care about what
they put out on their plates.
You will come back
again and again and again.
Hey, great job, man.
You're the bomb. Mmm.
Thanks.
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
to Syracuse, New York...
This is andouille
from who-ey?
...where an underground
bar and grill...
I like that.
...is cranking out
a spicy/sweet success story.
What is this,
the Paul Bunyan fajita platter?
You know, on
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives,"
we have found some funky joints
in some very unique locations.
Now, let's see --
auto-repair shop, a car wash,
I mean, even in a school bus.
So, I'm here in Syracuse,
New York, at Armory Square,
and I'm not that surprised
to find out that
there's a brewery/restaurant
that's gone subterranean.
And it's located
in an old pickle warehouse.
This is Empire Brewing Company.
WOMAN: Bentley burger.
Empire's definitely
a local favorite.
The atmosphere is fun.
The beer is fantastic.
Big Mamou up.
MAN: There's definitely
items on the menu here
that I don't think you'll find
anywhere else.
Very eclectic,
but it's all very good.
KATLESKI:
Plating up the feta chicken.
FIERI: And it's all from the
mind of owner David Katleski...
Sweet fire
is three minutes.
...a self-taught chef,
who left a money-making career
back in '94
to pursue his passion.
I was doing a lot of lease
negotiations with restaurants
and just fell in love
with the restaurant business.
So along with
Head Brewer Tim Butler...
...these guys are pairing unique
beers with eclectic recipes,
like this crazy combo
of Cajun and Tex-Mex.
Sweet fire fajitas.
They are unbelievable.
We created something
called sweet fire.
And what we do is
we slice andouille sausage,
which is the fire.
This is andouille
from who-ey?
from Nodine Smokehouse
in Danbury, Connecticut.
We add equal amounts
of brown sugar and molasses.
So, we toss this, and we coat it
evenly throughout.
And then we let it marinate
for 24 hours.
Really?
And it's converted the next day.
So, we do this every day.
Who came up
with this crazy idea?
Me.
This is whacked.
What in the wild, wild world
of sports is going on here?
Well, part of our fajitas
is the marinated onions
and peppers.
Magical.
We start with our onions.
Sliced grilled peppers.
And then
we make our marinade.
You start with orange juice
and soy sauce.
Olive oil.
We have our minced garlic.
Brown sugar.
Black pepper.
Fresh cilantro.
So, we mix it together, and then
we throw a ladle of this
on top
of our grilled vegetables.
So, it just gets a little brief
introduction to it like this?
These are good to go.
And then heat them up
and they're ready to go.
Correct.
I like that.
All right,
so, we got the sausage.
[ Sizzling ]
You're gonna bring those
up to temp,
get them nice and warm,
and then we're gonna finish them
in the salamander.
Peppers and onions
on the sizzle platter.
What do you want them,
on the sizzle platter?
Yep.
Sizzle, sizzle.
We're gonna break them down
just a hair.
We're gonna caramelize
the sugars into the meat,
and it's gonna put
this little, black edge
right around the outside of
each one of the sausage rings.
All right, so,
sausage looking good.
Look at that.
Leave that right there.
We'll get our underliner.
It's the Paul Bunyan
fajita platter?
How many is this for,
6 or 12?
This is a one serve.
One person?
Here, put a little
shredded cheddar Jack.
And we sell it.
[ Chuckles ]
That's it.
All right.
All the little things --
marinating it in molasses
and brown sugar,
roasting the onions
and the peppers,
and then adding
the citrus marinade --
all those little twists
make it something
that you probably
haven't had before.
Sweet, heat, crunchy veggies,
soft tortillas.
Yeah.
Nice job.
Sweet fire fajita.
WOMAN: There are so many
different flavors going on.
The sausage is obviously
the showpiece, but, you know,
everything just kind of
works together really well.
It's fantastic. Delicious.
WOMAN: The food is great.
It's succulent.
Everybody's taste buds
are gonna be touched
when they come down here.
Sunday brunch
or a Sunday brew.
It's always on the money.
It's just so much fun.
We love it.
David does a fantastic job.
How do you
put all this together?
Surround myself
with great people.
That's my best line.
Yep.
Kudos, my brother.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more Triple-D
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Hey, listen, man.
I'm just trying to get
in the flow of things.
The sunglasses --
you got that all wrong.
On my head? Come on.
That's way too "Baywatch."