HEY, EVERYBODY.
I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
THIS TRIP...
YOU'RE GONNA START HEARING
SOME FUNNY SOUNDS.
...GET READY
FOR THE UNEXPECTED....
WHAT IS
GOING ON RIGHT NOW?
...IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK.
MY MOUTH IS FIRING UP.
THE BASEMENT COLLEGE JOINT...
THIS MIGHT BE ONE OF THE
FUNKIEST THINGS I'VE EVER TRIED.
...GETTING WIGGY-WIGGY...
I THINK THIS IS GENIUS.
...WITH THE WAFFLES.
THAT IS JUST,
IN SO MANY WAYS, WEIRD.
WEIRD CAN BE COOL.
IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY...
LOOK AT THAT THING.
...THE SIDEWALK CUBAN SPOT...
THIS IS THE FIRST CULINARY CAVE
OF FLAVORTOWN.
...SERVING UP
SOME SERIOUS SURPRISES.
RISE UP.
CAN YOU FEEL IT?
CAN YOU FEEL IT, MY BROTHER?
AND IN DUCK, NORTH CAROLINA...
IT'S
A FUNKY, LITTLE JOINT
CONNECTED TO
A GAS-STATION CONVENIENCE STORE.
...TAKING TAKE-OUT...
YOUR STEAMER POT'S READY.
THANK YOU.
...TO A WHOLE NOTHER LEVEL.
IT IS DECADENT.
I KNOW YOU WISH
YOU COULD TRY SOME,
BUT I'M SO SORRY
ABOUT YOUR ALLERGY...
TO EATING OFF MY PLATE.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW,
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS, & DIVES."
ON THE ROAD TO FLAVORTOWN,
I SAY IT ALL THE TIME --
IF IT'S FUNKY, I'LL FIND IT.
I'M HERE IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK,
RIGHT BY THE CAMPUS --
THIS IS CALLED S.U. HILL --
TO CHECK OUT
A JOINT THAT'S FUNKY.
HOW FUNKY, YOU ASK?
SO FUNKY,
IT'S CALLED FUNK 'N WAFFLES.
♪ WAIT, WAIT, WAIT ♪
(funk music plays)
(singing indistinctly)
THIS IS LIKE
ADULT VERSION OF WAFFLES.
FALAFEL WAFFLE.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT.
♪ WAIT, WAIT, WAIT ♪
WHO RUNS AROUND WITH
A BUNCH OF WAFFLE IRONS?
(man) THESE GUYS.
(Fieri) SYRACUSE GRADS
KYLE COREA AND ADAM GOLD.
WE THREW THESE CRAZY HOUSE
PARTIES WHEN WE WERE IN COLLEGE.
I'D BE DEEJAYING
WITH MY BUDDY,
AND MY BUSINESS PARTNER,
KYLE, WOULD BE SLINGING
WAFFLES AT THE BAR.
GOT YOUR BEER,
YOU GOT YOUR WAFFLE.
REALLY?
JUST HANDING THEM OUT.
AND IN 2007,
THEY MADE IT LEGIT,
AND KEPT IT UNDERGROUND
WHEN THEY OPENED THIS JOINT
IN THE BASEMENT.
(Fieri)
SAVORY WAFFLES AND BREAKFAST
WAFFLES AND LUNCH WAFFLES.
I MEAN,
FRIED CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
BATTERED, FRIED CHICKEN ON TOP
OF A FRESH, BUTTERMILK WAFFLE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME BUTTERMILK BATTER HERE.
FOR?
THE FRIED CHICKEN
AND WAFFLE DISH.
AND THE BATTER IS FOR...
FOR THE WAFFLE.
WE'RE ALSO GONNA USE THE BATTER
FOR THE CHICKEN.
THAT'S LIKE CHICKEN AND WAFFLES
TO ANOTHER LEVEL.
IT IS.
WE'RE GONNA START
WITH THE BUTTERMILK FIRST.
I'M GONNA POUR THIS MILK
RIGHT HERE.
NEXT UP, WE'RE GONNA BRING
THIS THING TO TEMP.
GONNA USE
THE ESPRESSO MACHINE STEAM WARM.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
OUR OWN BUTTERMILK.
LIVING ON THE EDGE.
ALL RIGHT,
SO NOW, LEMON JUICE.
IT'S GONNA TURN THIS INTO
OUR BUTTERMILK.
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED
TO MIX IT.
WE'RE GONNA
SEPARATE SOME EGGS,
LIKE THIS STYLE.
GANGSTER.
OH, YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA WHISK THESE EGG
WHITES TILL THEY'RE A BIT FOAMY.
AND NOW WE'RE GONNA MIX THE
BUTTERMILK AND THE EGG WHITES.
THROW THEM IN THERE.
I'M GONNA WHISK
THE YOLKS A BIT.
SO, WE ARE GOING TO ADD
THE YOLKS AND THE BUTTER
TOGETHER
INTO THE REST OF THE WET MIX.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S KEEP THIS THING POPPING.
DRY TIME.
WE'RE GONNA START WITH
OUR LOCAL, ORGANIC,
ALL-PURPOSE WHITE FLOWER.
WE'RE GONNA THROW IN SUGAR.
ALL RIGHT, WE GOT SALT
AND THE BAKING POWDER.
OKAY, THEN I'M GONNA WHISK IT UP
A LITTLE BIT.
PUT THE WET IN THE DRY MIX.
AND NOW THE WAFFLE BATTER'S
READY TO GO.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE
SOME FRIED CHICKEN WINGS.
FIRST WE'RE GONNA MARINADE
THE WINGS IN BUTTERMILK?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE GONNA
LET IT SOAK OVERNIGHT.
NEXT UP,
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A DREDGE.
ORGANIC A.P.
SOME BREAD CRUMBS.
PAPRIKA.
CAYENNE.
JOINK.
JOINK?
YEAH.
THEY HEAR THAT
ON THE "SCOOBY-DOO."
IT'S ALWAYS "ZOINK."
THAT'S YOU'RE OWN LITTLE...
GARLIC POWDER.
NEW SOUND?
SCIBBLE-WAM.
(chuckles)
KOSHER SALT.
BLACK PEPPER.
LET'S WHISK THESE GUYS UP.
SO, THAT'S THE DREDGE.
SO, LET'S GET SOME OF THIS.
LOOK AT
THAT FOAMY FROTHING.
SEE, IT'S KIND OF CHANGING
A LITTLE BIT, IT THICKENED UP.
WE'RE GOING TO LOAD IT UP
IN THIS GUY.
THIN THIS NOW WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF WHOLE MILK.
THAT'S JUST SO 'CAUSE
IT WOULD BE WAY TOO COATY.
RIGHT. STIR IT UP.
NOW IT'S THIN ENOUGH.
TIME TO BATTER THESE WINGS.
GO.
LET'S GET THIS UP IN HERE.
ALL RIGHT, THERE'S OUR SIX.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE
THIS BUTTERMILK BATTER
AND WE'RE GONNA SOFTEN
THEM HERE.
THEY'RE GONNA RAGE IN THERE
FOR A SEC.
THROW THEM IN THE DREDGE.
WE'RE GONNA PLACE IT
RIGHT HERE.
GOT ALL SIX OF THESE GUYS.
NOW WE'RE GONNA DROP IT.
WE'RE GONNA DROP A BUTT.
A WHAT?
A BUTT.
SHORT FOR BUTTERMILK.
DROP THE BUTT!
DROPPING THE BUTT.
THAT'S SO THIN.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN MAKE A LITTLE MESS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THERE WE GO.
AND WE'RE GONNA SPIN IT.
THERE'S ANOTHER MOVE
THAT WE DO HERE.
SO, WE DROP IT LIKE THIS.
THAT WAY, WHEN IT WANTS
TO EXPAND, IT'S LOCKED IN.
YOU'RE GONNA START
HEARING SOME FUNNY SOUNDS.
(squealing)
WHAT IS GOING ON
RIGHT NOW?
'CAUSE
IT'S STILL URGLING.
URGLING IS THE TERM?
IT'S URGLING?
I CLEARLY SHOULD JUST
WRITE, A NEW DICTIONARY
FOR THIS RESTAURANT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
THE FUNK 'N DICTIONARY.
ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN MAKE THE SAUCE.
OUR HOUSE SPECIAL SAUCE.
GET SOME MAPLE SYRUP
UP IN HERE.
HOT SAUCE.
WORD.
AND CINNAMON.
INTERESTING.
GONNA GIVE THIS
A LITTLE WHISK.
OKAY.
KIND OF INCORPORATE IT.
THAT'S OUR SAUCE.
THESE WINGS ARE READY.
WOW, LOOK
HOW NICE THAT LOOKS.
HERE IS
THE CHICKEN AND WAFFLES.
I WANT TO JUST TRY
THE WING BY ITSELF.
MMM.
FRIED CHICKEN
IS RIGHTEOUS, MAN.
SO, IS THERE AN APPROPRIATE WAY
THAT YOU SEE --
I MEAN, I'D FEEL SACRILEGE
TO EAT THIS WITH A FORK.
I'M GONNA GO WITH THIS.
KIND OF
DOUBLE-FISTING IT.
YES.
THE WAFFLE'S DYNAMITE.
NICE AND CRISP.
GET THE BUTTERMILK, YOU GET THE
LITTLE SOUR COMING THROUGH THAT.
THE FRIED CHICKEN
IS SWEET, CRISPY, SPICY.
I MEAN,
JUST ALL THE COMPONENTS OF IT.
AND THEN THE SYRUP.
I MEAN, THAT'S JUST
WHAT PUSHES IT OVER THE TOP.
MMM.
I'M GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
(man) IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S REALLY CRUNCHY,
AND THAT'S WHY I LIKE IT.
I LOVE HOT SAUCE
AND MAPLE SYRUP.
IT'S ONE
OF MY FAVORITE THINGS.
AND FOR THE ULTIMATE COMFORT
FOOD, THE BIRD IS THE WORD.
(waitress) JIVE TURKEY.
A THANKSGIVING DINNER
ON TOP OF A WAFFLE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE JIVE TURKEY,
AND THAT STARTS OUT
WITH OUR STUFFING BATTER.
SOME CUBED-UP BREAD, CELERY...
A LITTLE
CARAMELIZED ONION.
I GOT OUR EGGS
AND ROSEMARY.
KOSHER SALT.
LITTLE BIT
OF CHICKEN BROTH.
FRESH GROUND PEPPER.
SPIN THIS THING AROUND.
SO, THIS IS GONNA GO
IN A WAFFLE MAKER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS GUY'S READY TO GO.
LOAD THAT UP.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS BEFORE.
ALL RIGHT.
THAT IS JUST,
IN SO MANY WAYS, WEIRD.
WEIRD CAN BE COOL.
AND NOW THAT THE WAFFLE'S DOWN,
WE'RE GONNA START PREPARING
EVERYTHING ELSE.
WE GOT SOME TURKEY
RIGHT HERE.
GOT IT.
THIS IS PROBABLY ONE OF THE
WEIRDEST WAFFLES I'VE EVER SEEN,
BUT I AM GOING TO
STEAL THIS.
ALL RIGHTY.
THIS GUY'S READY TO GO.
LET'S JUST TRIM HIM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
(sniffs) (sighs)
LET'S THROW
SOME OF THIS TURKEY ON THERE.
LET'S GET
SOME OF THESE MASHED POTATOES.
MY MOUTH IS FIRING UP.
OH, YEAH.
LET'S GET
A LITTLE BIT OF GRAVY ON IT.
WE'RE GONNA THROW
SOME CRANBERRY SAUCE.
THIS MIGHT BE ONE OF THE
FUNKIEST THINGS I'VE EVER TRIED.
(chuckling) YEAH.
(chuckles)
MMM!
SHUT THE FRONT DOOR.
OH, MY GOSH,
THAT IS KILLER.
THIS IS RIGHTEOUS.
THE STUFFING --
IT'S THE CRUNCH, THE TEXTURE.
MASHED POTATOES ARE LEGIT.
THAT IS FUNK 'N RIDICULOUS.
DUDE, THAT HAS CHANGED
THANKSGIVING FOR ME FOREVER.
I'M COMING HERE
FOR THANKSGIVING.
YOU'RE IN.
WELCOME TO FLAVORTOWN.
APPRECIATE IT.
♪ WAIT, WAIT, WAIT ♪
IT IS PROBABLY
THE MOST RIDICULOUS
FUNK 'N WAFFLE I'VE EVER HAD.
(woman) OUT OF THIS WORLD.
DELICIOUS.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
THIS MAY BE, LIKE,
THE CAPITAL OF FLAVORTOWN.
(funk music plays)
♪ WAIT, WAIT ♪
COMING UP...
DROP IT LIKE IT'S HOT.
WE'RE HEADING
TO HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY...
MY EYEBALLS
ARE SWEATING A BIT.
...FOR SOME OLD-SCHOOL
CUBAN CLASSICS.
THIS IS LIKE CUBAN PLUS.
(Fieri)
I'M HERE ON WASHINGTON STREET.
NOW, THIS IS,
LIKE, THE MAIN DRAG HERE
IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
AND I'M RIGHT ACROSS
THE HUDSON RIVER
FROM NEW YORK CITY.
NOW, THIS AREA IS LOADED WITH
GREAT ETHNIC RESTAURANTS,
BUT WHEN I HEAR THAT
THERE'S A CUBAN RESTAURANT,
YOU KNOW I GOT TO CHECK IT OUT.
THIS IS LA ISLA.
ONE PICADILLO,
ONE ARROZ CON POLLO,
ONE CAMARONES ENCENDIDO.
GOOD CUBAN FOOD. MAKES YOU
PUT A SMILE ON YOUR FACE.
WORLD-CLASS FLAVORS
AND A DOWN-HOME EXPERIENCE.
JUST WHAT CHEF OMAR GINER
DREAMED OF AS A KID.
HE USED TO TELL ME ALL THE TIME,
"I'M GONNA BE A CHEF.
I'M GONNA HAVE
MY OWN RESTAURANT."
HERE IT IS.
SOMETIMES DREAMS DO COME TRUE,
AND IN '96, OMAR AND HIS WIFE
BOUGHT THIS NEIGHBORHOOD JOINT
WITH HER FAMILY.
WHEN OMAR TOOK OVER,
IT WAS A WHOLE NEW FLAVOR.
WHICH MEANT AUTHENTIC CUBAN
WITH TIPS FROM THE EXPERTS.
MOM, GRANDMA,
MOTHER-IN-LAW.
MOTHER-IN-LAW?
ABSOLUTELY.
WHO TURNED HIM ON TO ONE
OF HER FAMILY FAVORITES.
TASAJO CON BONIATO.
PICK UP.
(woman) TASAJO IS AMAZING.
SHREDDED BEEF WITH THE OREGANO,
THE SPICES, THE TOMATO SAUCE.
IT'S JUST WONDERFUL.
WHAT DO WE GOT HERE?
SALTED, DRY, CURED BEEF.
IT'S A CHRISTMAS ORNAMENT.
FIRST I'LL TAKE
THIS PIECE OF STRING OFF.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
JUST PUT IT IN A PAN,
AND WE'RE JUST GONNA ADD
SOME FRESH, COOL WATER.
AND WE'LL BRING IT UP TO A BOIL
FOR ABOUT THREE HOURS.
IT'S VERY TOUGH.
BUT IT IS COW.
IT IS STEER.
IT IS COW, YEAH.
YOU SURE?
IT IS -- (moos)
YEAH.
DID YOU JUST MAKE A NOISE?
UH...(laughs)
SO, HERE'S THE TASAJO
THAT WE'VE COOKED.
IT'S LIKE DRIED BEEF.
EXACTLY.
SO, WE'LL JUST
PUT THIS IN HERE.
IT KIND OF HELPS TO SHRED IT UP
A LITTLE BIT FINER.
START THE PAN WITH
A LITTLE EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE OIL.
GONNA DROP IN OUR ONIONS.
GARLIC.
ATTABOY.
COUPLE BAY LEAFS.
SEASON IT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF BLACK PEPPER.
A LITTLE TOUCH
OF SMOKED PAPRIKA.
A LITTLE TOMATO PUREE.
AND THEN, RIGHT FROM HERE,
I'M GONNA DROP MY MEAT INSIDE.
THEN WE'LL JUST ADD
A LITTLE WINE HERE.
LET THIS COOK DOWN...
BELOW THE FIRE.
I'LL PUT A COVER ON IT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA SERVE THIS
WITH SWEET POTATOES.
YEAH.
THESE, WE BOIL
A LITTLE BIT OF MILK,
A LITTLE SALT,
A LITTLE SUGAR.
AND SOME MORO.
MORO?
BLACK BEANS AND RICE
THAT'S MIXED TOGETHER.
IT'S A WHITE SWEET POTATO?
THIS IS A WHITE SWEET POTATO,
YEAH.
SO, WE HAVE
OUR TASAJOS READY.
SO, WE'RE JUST GONNA TAKE
THAT AND PILE THAT UP HERE.
THIS IS CRAZY.
I'VE NEVER SEEN THIS.
A LITTLE CHIVE OIL
OVER THE TOP.
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
WE'RE GONNA TOP IT
WITH FRIED SWEET POTATO.
LIKE A SUSHI ROLL.
DUDE, THIS IS A HIT.
MMM.
GLAD YOU LIKE IT.
YOU GOT SALTY,
YOU GOT SWEET.
YOU GOT TENDER, CHEWY RICE,
AND SOFT, SILKY BEANS.
SOUNDS LIKE A EULOGY
IN THIS PLACE.
(laughs)
YOU GOT BEAUTIFUL GREEN,
AND YOU GOT A MELLOW RED.
YOU SEE THE CRISPY ONIONS,
AND YOU GET THE SWEET --
RISE UP.
CAN YOU FEEL IT?
CAN YOU FEEL IT, MY BROTHER?
THE MAN.
(laughs)
(man) THIS IS REAL MMMs.
REALLY, LIKE, AUTHENTIC.
LIKE, I'M SAYING IT
EVERY TIME I'M TAKING A BITE.
MMM.
NOW, THAT'S
THE KIND OF LOVE YOU GET
WHEN YOU GO REAL DEAL.
(Giner) ONE PICADILLO.
THIS IS DELICIOUS.
I'VE NEVER HAD THIS HERE BEFORE.
ARROZ CON POLLO.
PICK UP.
THEY'VE EVEN GOT A CUBAN SPIN
ON MEAT AND POTATOES.
PAPA RELLENA SALSA RANCHERA.
PICK UP.
OKAY, WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
THE GROUND FILLING THAT WE MAKE
FOR LA PAPA RELLENA.
WE FRESHLY GRIND
OUR BEEF IN-HOUSE.
OKAY.
HEAT UP OUR PAN, AND WE'RE GONNA
ADD OUR OLIVE OIL IN THERE.
DROP IN OUR DICED ONIONS,
GARLIC, OUR BAY LEAF IN THERE,
OREGANO.
THIS IS CUMIN THAT WE TOAST
AND WE GRIND IN-HOUSE.
THAT'S JUST
MY LITTLE TWIST ON IT.
AND THEN WE ALSO ADD A LITTLE
SMOKED PAPRIKA, AS WELL.
ADD OUR GROUND BEEF.
NOW WE'RE GONNA HIT
THE TOMATO PASTE.
COOK THAT OUT --
GIVE IT A LITTLE COLOR.
WE'LL ADD A LITTLE SALT,
AND WE'LL ADD SOME WHITE WINE.
GIVE IT
A LITTLE LIQUID THERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA ASSEMBLE
OUR PAPA RELLENA.
WE GOT THE MASHED POTATOES.
MASHED POTATOES.
THE PICADILLO THAT WE COOLED.
SO, WHAT WE'RE
JUST GONNA DO IS
GET OURSELVES A NICE
LITTLE BALL HERE OF POTATO.
(whistles)
SO, IF YOU'RE LATE FOR WORK,
YOU GET STUCK WITH THIS JOB.
THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
WE'RE GONNA DROP IT
IN THE EGG WASH.
I'M GONNA USE A SPOON,
SO THAT WAY,
I CAN KEEP OFF MY HANDS.
NEXT, THEY GO
INTO THE FINE PANKO.
BACK IN AGAIN.
AND THEN INTO
THE COARSE PANKO.
OKAY.
NOW GOES THE FRYER.
FOR ABOUT FOUR MINUTES?
FOUR MINUTES
TILL IT'S GOLDEN BROWN.
OH, BOY.
RANCHERA SAUCE.
(imitates Cuban accent)
RANCHERA SAUCE?
RANCHERA SAUCE.
SO, LOOK AT THAT.
THIS IS THE FIRST DISCOVERED
CULINARY CAVE OF FLAVORTOWN.
MMM. OH.
THAT SAUCE IS RIDICULOUS.
MMM!
BUT I THINK THAT THE COMBINATION
THAT YOU PUT TOGETHER,
ALONG WITH THIS MEAT
AND THE POTATO
AND THE LITTLE CRUNCHY
CRISPINESS ON THE OUTSIDE
FROM THE PANKO --
THAT IS KILLER, DUDE.
MMM.
CHEF, AWESOME JOB.
MY EYEBALLS
ARE SWEATING A BIT.
PAPA'S READY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
MAKES IT SO GOOD?
IT'S AUTHENTIC.
THIS IS LIKE CUBAN PLUS.
CHEF, YOU'RE THE BOMB.
AWESOME. AWESOME.
THANKS, MAN.
UP NEXT...
ENJOY THE LOCAL FAIR.
WE'RE HEADING TO DUCK
ON THE NORTH CAROLINA COAST...
(typewriter clacking, dings)
...WHERE A DRIVE-THROUGH
GAS STATION...
AND YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO
GET OUT OF YOUR CAR TO GET IT?
...IS SERVING UP
KILLER FRESH SEAFOOD.
THIS SCALLOP
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
I'M HERE IN THE OUTER BANKS
OF NORTH CAROLINA
IN A LITTLE TOWN CALLED DUCK,
AND I'M HERE
FOR A FAMILY REUNION.
WHILE I'M HERE,
I GOT TO SEE IF THERE'S
ANY HIDDEN TRIPLE-D JOINTS,
SO I CHECKED THIS PLACE OUT.
IT'S NEXT TO A GAS STATION,
IT'S GOT A DRIVE-THROUGH,
BUT DON'T LET
THOSE THINGS SCARE YOU.
THEY GOT A GREAT MENU
AND SOME KILLER SEAFOOD.
THIS IS CRAVINGS.
(man) IT'S VERY FRESH.
IT COMES RIGHT FROM THE WATER,
SO YOU KNOW YOU'RE GETTING
THE HIGHEST-QUALITY FOOD.
AND LOBSTER SAUCE.
I REALLY DON'T KNOW
A PLACE THAT I CAN GET
CRAB CAKES AND DIESEL
IN THE SAME LOCATION.
I SORT OF THOUGHT
THEY HAD LOST THEIR MIND.
BUT OWNERS DAN LEWIS
AND SCOTT FOSTER
KNEW FOLKS AROUND DUCK
WOULDN'T JUDGE THIS BOOK
BY IT'S COVER.
OR A RESTAURANT
BY IT'S GAS STATION.
EXACTLY.
WE BASICALLY DESCRIBE IT
AS OUR VERSION,
OUR TAKE ON QUICK SERVICE.
THEIR VERSION INCLUDES
FRESH SEAFOOD
STRAIGHT FROM
THE DRIVE-UP WINDOW.
ORDERING IN --
SCALLOP DINNER.
THE SCALLOPS ARE SWEET,
TENDER, JUICY, AND JUST FRESH.
YOU CAN TELL THE STUFF
JUST CAME OUT OF THE SEA.
SO, THIS IS THE BEGINNING OF
MAKING THE LOBSTER BRANDY SAUCE.
YES.
ALL RIGHT, HIT IT.
I TAKE SOME SOFTENED BUTTER.
GONNA GO AHEAD
AND GET SOME GARLIC IN THERE.
ONIONS GO IN THERE.
LET THE ONIONS SWEAT
THE GARLIC.
OUTER BANKS SEA SALT.
ALL RIGHT.
AND I GO AHEAD AND HIT IT
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF ACID.
MAKE MY RUE NOW.
ABOUT THREE SCOOPS
OF FLOUR.
SO, 50/50.
SO, NOW I'M GONNA HIT IT
WITH SOME WINE.
AND IN GOES
OUR LOBSTER STOCK.
GONNA ADD
SOME HEAVY CREAM.
THEN I ADD THE BRANDY.
SO, WE'RE GONNA LET THIS GO,
LET IT REDUCE, HOLD IT COLD,
AND THEN WE'LL USE THAT
WHEN WE MAKE THE SCALLOPS.
YEP.
GOT IT.
SAUCE IS DONE.
YEAH.
OUTER BANKS SCALLOPS.
GORGEOUS-LOOKING SCALLOPS.
WORD.
A LITTLE BIT
OF CANOLA VEGETABLE OIL.
THESE GUYS JUST GO RIGHT IN.
SO, NOW YOU DON'T MESS
WITH THEM.
NO, YOU LITERALLY
DON'T WANT TO TOUCH THEM.
LET THEM SEAR ON BOTH SIDES.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
OUTER BANKS SALT.
YEP.
GET THEM SEARED ON ONE SIDE,
SEARED ON THE OTHER SIDE.
ALL RIGHT,
SO THEY'RE ALMOST DONE.
GONNA GO AHEAD
AND LAND OUR SAUCE.
THREE IN THE FRONT.
TWO IN THE BACK.
I'M GONNA PUT A LITTLE DAB
OF TRUFFLE OIL RIGHT ON TOP.
FRESH SCALLOP.
DON'T EVEN NEED TO CUT IT
WITH A KNIFE.
DUDE, I'M GONNA
TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THIS IS UP THERE IN SOME OF
THE BEST SCALLOPS I'VE EVER HAD.
'CAUSE THIS SCALLOP
IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
THE SAUCE, THE PREPARATION,
THE LITTLE BIT OF THE CRUST
ON THE OUTSIDE OF THE SCALLOP,
SUPER-HOT PAN.
THE TOUCH
OF THE TRUFFLE OIL.
IT IS DECADENT.
I KNOW YOU WISH
YOU COULD TRY SOME,
BUT I'M SO SORRY
ABOUT YOUR ALLERGY...
TO EATING OFF MY PLATE.
MMM.
(chuckles)
EXCELLENT, BROTHER.
VERY NICE JOB.
OH, WE AIN'T DONE AT DUCK.
WHEN WE COME BACK...
OH!
HELLO.
...WE'RE HEADING OUTSIDE...
(man) Welcome to Cravings.
What can I get for you today?
...AND STRAIGHT
TO THE DRIVE-THROUGH.
THANK YOU.
TRIPLE-D IS AT CRAVINGS
IN DUCK, NORTH CAROLINA,
ON THE OUTER BANKS,
WHERE SCOTT FOSTER AND DAN LEWIS
HAVE WORKED UP A KILLER COMBO,
CONNECTING A GAS STATION
TO A SEAFOOD SPOT.
GRILLED TUNA UP.
(woman) I'VE BEEN WITH SCOTT
AND DAN FROM THE BEGINNING.
THEY FIRST STARTED OUT
MAINLY WITH THE DRIVE-THROUGH.
(Man) Welcome to Cravings.
What can I get for you today?
THAT'S RIGHT --
A DRIVE-THROUGH.
SO, THEY CAN ORDER
THE WHOLE MENU?
THEY CAN GET ALL OF IT.
(Scott) OH, YEAH.
(chuckling) NOT BAD.
HI.
HOW ARE YOU TODAY?
GOOD.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
YOUR STEAMER POT'S READY.
THANK YOU.
IT'S A CAROLINA COAST
TRADITION --
A COOKING POT
LOADED TO THE HILL
WITH FRESH, LOCAL SEAFOOD.
I'D SAY FEED
A FAMILY OF SIX EASILY.
NOW THAT'S
MY KIND OF TAKE-OUT.
WONDERFUL WAY
TO ENJOY THE LOCAL FARE.
YOU SAID THAT
VERY NEWSCASTERISH.
(low voice)
ENJOY THE LOCAL FARE.
(normal voice) ALL RIGHT,
SO TELL US WHAT WE DO.
WE START OUT WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF ICE.
ICE IS IN THE BOTTOM
SO IT KEEPS IT COLD
AND IT ALSO WORKS
AS THE STEAMING LIQUID
FOR WHEN THIS GETS GOING.
EXACTLY, AND IF YOU WANT TO
THROW A BEER OR WINE IN THERE,
THAT'S YOUR PLEASURE.
LIVE ON THE EDGE.
EXACTLY.
CUT RED POTATOES,
SMOKED SAUSAGE.
WHAT KIND OF SAUSAGE?
THIS IS A SMOKED SAUSAGE FROM A
GUY NAMED LARRY IN FAYETTEVILLE,
AND, OF COURSE,
IT'S CALLED LARRY'S SAUSAGE.
NEXT, WE HAVE OUR FRESH,
LOCAL CORN ON THE COBB.
WE HAVE SOME WONDERFUL,
EASTERN SHORE OYSTERS,
MIDDLE-NECK CLAMS,
AND OF COURSE,
SOME CRAB LEGS.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
SNOW CRAB LEGS ARE VERY POPULAR
IN THE OUTER BANKS.
WE ALSO HAVE
THE FRESH, LOCAL SHRIMP.
NOW, THE REASON I'M PACKING THEM
IN A PLASTIC BAG
IS BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT
TO COOK THE SHRIMP
THE SAME AMOUNT OF TIME
AS YOU DO THE --
IT'LL BE TOUGH AS CAN BE.
EXACTLY.
WHAT IS
THAT SEASONING THERE?
THAT IS OLD BAY,
OF COURSE.
OKAY.
AND BUTTER AND COCKTAIL
TO GO ALONG WITH.
PUT THE LID ON IT.
LID ON.
AND THIS IS
HOW IT GOES HOME.
CAN YOU GET THIS ONE ROLLING?
OKAY.
OH!
HELLO.
TAKES ABOUT 20 MINUTES
FOR THE ICE TO MELT,
BUT ONCE IT STARTS STEAMING,
IT TAKES ROUGHLY
ABOUT A HALF HOUR,
AND THE SHRIMP WILL GO IN
ABOUT HALFWAY THROUGH
SO, AGAIN, THE SHRIMP
ARE NOT OVERCOOKED.
GOT IT.
AND SO, WE'RE READY TO GO.
GET YOURSELF A BIG TRAY.
AND JUST LET EVERYTHING
POUR RIGHT OUT.
OH, LOOK AT THE BROTH.
OH, THE BROTH IS FANTASTIC.
THE SHELLFISH BROTH,
THE SHRIMP BROTH,
YOU'VE GOT ALL THAT SAUSAGE.
THE SAUSAGE JUST FLAVORS
THE POTATOES SO WELL.
OKAY.
SO, THE IDEA IS THROW IT DOWN
ON THE TABLE, CRACK IT.
MMM.
LITTLE BIT OF LEMON JUICE.
SOMETHING ABOUT SHRIMP
THAT'S NOT BEEN FROZEN.
MMM.
OH, YEAH.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
THE FRESH, LOCAL SHRIMP.
(typewriter clacking, dings)
DING!
THERE'S A LOT GOING ON HERE.
FOUR BIG PIECES OF SAUSAGE,
POTATOES, THE CORN.
EXCELLENT.
AND YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO
GET OUT OF YOUR CAR TO GET IT?
NO, YOU CAN GET IT RIGHT THROUGH
THE DRIVE-THROUGH IF YOU LIKE.
PACKAGE DEAL, MAN.
ORDERING IN.
STEAMER POT FOR SIX.
HERE'S YOUR STEAMER POT.
(woman) IT'S SO SIMPLE TO DO.
THROW IT ON YOUR STOVE.
WHEN YOU'RE DONE, YOU'VE GOT
A FRESH, LOCAL-SEAFOOD FEAST.
GENTLEMEN,
THANKS FOR HAVING ME, MAN.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
CRAVINGS, WHAT AN AWESOME JOINT.
YOU GOT TO SEE THIS.
SO, THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE-D
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT WEEK
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS, & DIVES."
GUY, WE HAVE SIX MORE
TRIPLE-D LOCATIONS TO SHOOT.
I HAVE TO HAVE YOU.
I'VE TOLD YOU.
I'M GOING ON VACATION
WITH MY FAMILY.
IT'S SIX LOCATIONS.
I NEED TWO WEEKS.
HOW DO I RUN A SHOW?
LISTEN, FIND SOMEBODY,
GIVE THEM THE SHADES,
GIVE THEM THE CAR,
FIND SOMEBODY.
I'LL SEE YOU IN TWO WEEKS.
THANKS.
OH, MAN.
WHERE DO WE...
I DON'T KNOW.
WILLIAM SHATNER.
WAIT.
HOW ABOUT THE ROCK?
YEAH.
COLIN FARRELL.
YES.
YES!
(laughs)
THAT'S IT.
(Fieri) I FORGOT TO SAY,
WHOEVER IT'S GONNA BE,
THEY'RE GONNA NEED THIS.
(laughs)
COLIN, WE'D LOVE TO HAVE YOU
ON TRIPLE-D ANYTIME, MAN.
YOU THE BOMB.
OW!
(chuckles)