Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Badass.
Can I say "badass"?
Yes,
you can say "badass."
...we're stacking on
the flavor...
What are you
talking about?
...and firing up the grill.
In Toronto, Canada...
Outstanding.
...a restored diner...
What you see
is what you get, baby.
...putting on the pork
and going big on burgers...
That's a fatty patty.
...with a holiday twist.
Christmas burger.
Then in Nags Head,
North Carolina...
Welcome back
to "Jungle Hour."
...the Caribbean seaside shack
bringing the heat
with the meat.
I'm gonna tell you what,
brother.
That chop's legit.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
So, I'm here
on Highway 12 South,
known as the beach road
in Nags Head, North Carolina,
in the Outer Banks.
Now, right past those houses
and over the dunes,
that's the Atlantic Ocean.
I mean, this is
one of the "go to" spots
for vacation on the east coast.
So, what can you expect?
Well, you get awesome beaches,
killer surf,
and great restaurants --
like this joint, Tortugas' Lie.
Grilled crawdads up.
MAN: It's got a lot
of Caribbean flavors.
They're delicious.
Fun to try and fun to eat.
And that's what keeps me
coming back.
Baja fish tacos.
It's just got
that beach feel.
FIERI:
Just what owners Bob Sanders
and Richard Welch were going for
when they opened the joint
in '89 --
complete with surfboards,
funky license plates,
and a name guaranteed
to stir up a conversation.
This name, Tortugas' Lie --
Wha-- wha--
Just after the Caribbean islands
and, you know,
it's where the turtles lie,
where they come tell stories
or they drink
too many Cayman cripplers.
What are you
talking about?
Exactly.
Cryptic message.
I've been in the sun
too long.
Emphasis on great local seafood
with a Caribbean flair.
FIERI: With Richard
going all Clark Kent
and manning the grill,
he's spreading Caribbean love
on local seafood, chicken,
and even pork.
Pork Antonio
up in the window.
MAN: It's awesome.
Nice and juicy.
You get a little bit of heat
out of it,
and then the jelly
just cools it right off.
What are we gonna make?
Dry jerk seasoning that's gonna
go on our pork chops.
All right.
Hit it up, man.
Kosher salt.
Sugar.
Ground thyme.
Granulated onion.
Habanero pepper.
Black pepper.
Here comes the traditions
of the jerk seasoning.
Allspice.
Nutmeg.
Should have
a little cinnamon coming in.
Cinnamon.
Little more Cayenne,
little more heat there.
You ever go outdoors
in a windstorm and do this?
[ Chuckles ]
North Carolina pork chop
here.
We're gonna put a little bit
of the dry rub on it.
And this dish
is called what?
Pork Antonio.
So, we're gonna let those
sit there
and just take a little bit
of a marinade from the dry rub,
just let that
kind of soak in the flavor.
While we do that,
what's up?
We're gonna top that with
some habanero-pepper jelly.
Getting all culinary gangster
on me. All right.
Little bit of sugar.
Red pepper.
Cold raisins, chopped.
Fresh habanero,
seeded and chopped.
Throw that
on the burner.
White vinegar.
Bring that to a boil.
We're gonna add
the pectin.
You need to work with this
kind of quick
because
it is gonna set up fast.
[ Whistles ]
And then
it is smoking-hot.
Whaa!
Okay.
Right on. Okay.
These chops are thin.
Right.
They're gonna go fast.
Yep. Couple minutes
on each side.
Nice.
All right,
we're putting the pepper jelly
on the pork chops here
now.
Kind of glazing it a bit?
Just a little.
Okay, so,
a little fresh, sautéed veg --
I like that.
You got it.
And then
some smashed reds.
All right,
there you have it.
Juicy chop.
I'm gonna tell you what,
brother.
Tell me, please.
That chop's legit.
It's juicy,
nice sear on the meat.
The dry rub is spicy and
definitely gets your attention.
The jelly
kind of smoothes it out,
adding a little bit
of the sugar
and a little bit
of its own heat.
Mashed potatoes
and fresh veg.
That's, like,
big-restaurant good.
Thank you.
Glad you like it.
"Like it"? I love it.
The pork is really tender.
Then there's this awesome jelly.
It gives a little bit of spice
and some sweetness.
FIERI: But these cats
are doing more
than just pleasing
the hungry beach crowd.
For them,
it's all about living the life.
So, I think I've got
you guys' thing figured out.
You guys are surf bums,
and you just wanted your
own place to come and hang out
where you didn't have
to just eat out of
the back of your car.
[ Chuckles ]
Have I cracked the code?
You got it. Exactly.
I dig it.
FIERI: When we come back,
we're getting a little more
of the surfer grind...
Oh, my goodness.
...and finding out that the bird
is definitely the word.
Off the hook.
FIERI:
For a classic post-surf spot,
it's hard to top Tortugas' Lie
in Nags Head Beach,
North Carolina.
That's because owners
Richard Welch and Bob Sanders
did a lot of living
in the Caribbean,
picking up waves and recipes,
like this house favorite.
Jerk chicken up.
Welcome back
to "Jungle Hour."
[ Both laugh ]
All right,
what are we making?
All right, we're gonna make
wet jerk seasoning here.
And the primary
ingredients --
green onion,
if you hadn't already guessed.
[ Whistles ]
So, are we gonna cook these
in the pot?
Nope. We're just gonna
process them.
We're gonna add
some water.
Now I'm gonna introduce you
to my little friend.
Did you just
go Tony Montana on me?
[ Whirring ]
I have never seen
this amount
of green-onion sludge
in my life.
All right.
We're there.
This is gonna set
for about four or five days
so all that water
will drain back out of it.
You took
this many green onions...
Right.
...squeezed all the water out,
and this is now what we have.
That is what we have.
Let's get it going.
All right, let's do it.
We're gonna sauté up
some habaneros.
Okay.
And they will flame up.
There we go.
That's what we want.
So, the scallions
are gonna go back in the pot.
We're gonna add
sauteed habaneros,
roasted red peppers,
garlic, oil.
There you go.
Apple cider vinegar.
Kosher salt.
Ketchup.
Thyme.
Allspice.
Nutmeg.
Cinnamon.
Shallots.
We hit it with
the gigantic immersion blender.
[ Whirring ]
That chicken
has been brined?
Yep.
We're gonna
stuff it with some butter.
We're gonna do the same thing
with the jerk.
The wet jerk.
Hit it was
a little bit of the dry spice.
All little
of the dry jerk.
Right.
We're gonna mark it.
Okay.
We'll flip it over.
Mark that side?
Hit the other side.
And then into the oven.
And at
what temperature?
350 for a half-hour.
So, we're ready
to plate our jerk chicken.
Bit of sour cream
to cool it down a little bit.
And a little
pineapple chutney for you.
Mmm.
[ Laughing ] Oh.
Great heat.
Not too spicy.
Green onion really plays
a major role in this dish.
Like that butter
under the skin.
Moist, not dried out.
You get the allspice.
You get some of that cinnamon.
Get a little bit
of that habanero...
with this
pineapple chutney.
The food's ridiculous,
man.
Thanks, man.
Seriously.
Off the hook.
Jerk chicken.
So, once in a while
on "Triple D,"
I get, like,
a really special guest.
This buddy of mine, I met him
flying to the Persian Gulf
onto the U.S.S. Enterprise --
He's a pilot.
He's Commander
Michael "Dano" Bratley
and his beautiful wife,
Kim.
What do you guys think?
Oh, the pork chop's
delicious.
Are you kidding me?
This chicken is on point.
Salty yet spicy.
Doing it up right.
Can't go wrong
coming to this place.
Always, always good meals.
FIERI: Are we gonna get bigger?
This is tiny.
I have a feeling I'll be
making more jerk chicken.
You know what? You better
buy a green onion farm.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up...
What you see
is what you get, baby.
...we're headed
to Toronto, Canada...
Getting
all medieval on it.
...where a restored
retro diner
is holding all the aces
with the menu.
I just shove it all in
at one time.
You know,
one of my favorite things
about "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives"
is the history of these joints,
so I'm in Toronto, Canada,
on the west side of Parkdale
in an area known as Roncy,
to check out a joint
that started as a diner.
Then it became
a Chinese restaurant,
and then it was closed
for 30 years
until two friends found it.
They kept the name
and reopened it.
This is The Ace.
Got two burgers
on the grill.
It's comfort food.
It's delicious.
Picking up one steak frites,
please.
MAN: Very simple food,
but it's prepared with
a more sophisticated sense.
You're gonna walk away
pretty happy.
FIERI: And full.
Because, since 2011,
owners Maggie Ruhl
and Greg Boggs
have been aiming to please
in spades.
How'd you
find the place?
Walked around the corner
one day,
and the curtains
were open,
and it was
an old, beautiful diner.
We wanted to sort of just have
something a bit more upscale.
So, they hired
Chef Peter McKnight
to combine the greasy spoon
with a silver one.
Tell me about
your food style.
It's well-executed
comfort food.
What you see
is what you get, baby.
Exactly.
That all comes together
in this
"nothing up my sleeve,"
classic pork dish.
The pork belly.
Tender and juicy.
It's a meaty pork belly.
So, what are we
making first?
It's a roasted
pork belly.
Work it.
So, I'm gonna just
score this pork belly.
Now, is this farm to table?
We got anything local?
We use Ontario pork, yeah.
It's good stuff.
So, we season with
an equal amount of
salt and sugar.
We're gonna do both sides,
and then we're gonna just
go right into the oven
on a rack
for 90 minutes or so.
Okay, just gonna roast it off,
render it down.
Absolutely.
So, the pork belly's
in now.
The pork belly comes with
a warm potato salad.
This is the rendered pork fat
from our belly.
This just
brings the dish together.
So, pork fat.
Red onions.
We're gonna just season.
A little bit of salt and pepper.
We're gonna
add in our potatoes.
So, this is
a German-style potato salad.
It's just a take on --
I mean, just warm it up.
We're gonna add
grainy mustard in here.
A little bit
of red wine vinegar.
And then a little bit of chive
for some beautiful green.
And we're good.
So, we got
our finished pork belly here.
We do
a pretty healthy portion.
Now you're gonna take it,
hit it in the deep fryer
and really crisp it up.
And how long
will that go?
2 1/2 minutes or so.
Okay, so, we're starting
with the potato salad
just in the corner here.
We're gonna add
our celery and radish salad
to the other side.
A little pork belly
that's just crisped up.
I'm gonna dip it here, and then
we're gonna just slice it.
And this is...?
Sriracha, soy,
and vinegar.
Got it.
Very nice.
Mmm.
I just shove it all in
at one time.
This is the kind of food
I want to find
in funky, little joints.
You almost have
a couple different styles
of food going on --
the German style,
a little bit of Asian influence
'cause of the soy.
You got the acid
with the salt with the sugar
with the caramelization
along with this rich,
unctuous pork belly.
Outstanding.
Excellent.
The best hunk of bacon
I've ever had in my life.
FIERI: Served up at a joint
that prides itself
on being a throwback.
It's got the best ambience,
right?
Chinese restaurant.
Badass.
Can I say "badass"?
Yes, you can
say "badass."
This opened what?
1955.
'55.
Is the counter original?
You can see the elbows...
Where the elbows
are rubbed in.
For 50 years.
I love it.
FIERI:
With this kind of history,
old-school favorites
like mac and cheese
fit right in...
...in their own,
so twisted way.
McKNIGHT: Pickup --
one mac and cheese burger.
Cheesy, rich, delicious.
It's great.
What are we making?
Well, we're gonna do
our mac and cheese burger.
With mac and cheese?
Absolutely.
Okay.
We start with
a very good Béchamel sauce.
Generous amount
of butter.
A little shallot.
Seasoned with
salt and pepper.
And then
we're gonna build a roux.
We're going to add in flour,
some whipping cream.
We're just gonna
whisk that together.
And then we'll just simmer
that out for a little while.
Finish it with
a little bit of aged cheddar.
Checking it.
Mmm.
We're gonna add
our cooked pasta in the mix.
And then we add in
a good amount of cheese curds.
Like, we're gonna get
those cheese pulls.
We're gonna get
that stretchy mac and cheese.
We're gonna
move to our patty.
This is ground
Black Angus chuck.
I do a puree of Dijon mustard,
rosemary, and onion
to flavor this beef.
Okay.
We're gonna do
a couple eggs in here.
Season
with salt and pepper.
And then just bind with
a little bit of bread crumbs,
just to hold these
together.
Getting all medieval
on it.
I'm just gonna form a patty.
6 1/2 ounces or so.
I like a good
baseball-sized burger.
So, we're just gonna cook this
for about 12 minutes,
put some nice lines
on this burger, flip it over,
and then we'll build.
We got our toasted bun.
We're gonna start mac and cheese
on the bottom here.
Spicy ketchup
on the top bun.
75% ketchup
and then like 25% hot sauce.
Sriracha?
Yeah.
Add our patty on there.
That's a fatty patty.
Tomato, lettuce,
crispy onions.
House-cut fries.
Finish the burger
with the steak knife.
Just gonna build that plate
right there.
It's a big burger.
All right.
Do I have any
right here?
Where's
that beach towel?
[ Laughs ]
The mac and cheese
is super-creamy.
This is creaminess
with a little more texture
because of the macaroni.
Absolutely.
My favorite part about it --
believe it or not --
that spicy ketchup.
Got the salt.
You got the creamy/buttery.
You got the richness
of the beef.
And what cuts it all,
that little kick,
that little acid kick
that's coming through.
Really nice.
If you're gonna do
a burger
and you're gonna put
signature to it,
that's the way to go.
Good job, Peter.
Thank you very much.
All right,
so, the mac and cheese burger.
We had the bacon.
You've got to have something
secret up your sleeve.
Do you have
another burger?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
Okay, well,
don't tell me what it is.
When we come back,
we're hanging out at The Ace
in Toronto, Canada.
See you in a bit.
Welcome back --
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives"
hanging out in Toronto, Canada,
at The Ace.
Now, this is my buddy Peter
over here.
We have had
some fantastic bacon.
We had a bomb
mac and cheese burger.
And now?
Christmas burger.
A stuffing center
in a turkey burger.
All right.
Get us started.
So, we got a mixture
of olive oil and butter.
And we're gonna do
some mirepoix --
just carrots, celery, onions,
finely chopped.
We're gonna add
some dried sage.
Salt and pepper.
And we got some chopped
whole-wheat bread.
So, we're gonna add in
our fresh sage.
And you got to love sage
in stuffing.
Oh, yeah.
So, we have
a turkey stock here.
So, you make
your own stock.
And short of making the ketchup,
you do it yourself.
Pretty much.
We're gonna simmer it up
for a little while,
let all that liquid
sort of come together.
We're gonna cool it
out on a tray,
and we'll begin to build
our burger.
'Cause we can't put
hot stuffing into...
The raw poultry.
No turkey seviche.
No way.
Now?
We're gonna build
our cranberry compote.
We're gonna use
some fresh cranberries.
We're gonna do cinnamon stick
and vanilla bean.
Brown sugar.
Fresh, chopped orange.
Orange zest.
Orange juice.
And then we're just
gonna kick it up
with some Jack Daniel's.
Oh, yes.
[ Chuckles ]
So,
that just simmers down.
Absolutely.
Cooks down.
Yep.
All right, so, we're gonna build
our Christmas burger.
We got ground turkey.
This is a 50/50 split of...
Thigh and breast?
Absolutely.
Very nice.
Good fat mixture.
We're gonna go three eggs.
Salt and pepper.
Once again, our puree of onions,
rosemary, and Dijon mustard.
And do a generous amount of
bread crumbs just to bind this.
Get medieval.
Absolutely, yeah.
Get in there,
mix it all up.
Form a patty from here.
So, we're gonna go
into a ring form.
And what I do is,
I'm gonna take out a piece,
because this is gonna be
our cover.
And we're gonna build up
the sides, create a bottom.
And we have a ball
of this stuffing
that we've already
previously done.
We're gonna pack that in.
And we're gonna turn this
into a flat piece,
a cover for that.
So, this is like
a very technical form
of making a Juicy Lucy.
No cheese inside of it,
but it does have stuffing.
The boys at the Nook
in St. Paul, Minnesota...
Got a Juicy Nookie,
fried onions.
...this is something
they would dig.
Ted, Mike, you see this?
What do you think?
BOTH: Sweet.
That's what I thought.
All right,
so, next up?
A little seasoning
on the outside.
A little bit
of olive oil.
And this gets roasted
in the oven
just to keep with that
Christmas burger sort of feel.
Roast turkey,
roast stuffing.
Yeah, 'cause I always have
a roast Christmas burger.
[ Laughs ]
So, we're starting
with a toasted bun.
We're gonna go mayo.
We're gonna do
lettuce and tomato.
Our cranberry compote.
Our roasted turkey patty.
[ Whistles ]
And we're gonna skewer just with
a couple rosemary sprigs
just to keep it together.
And I'm gonna split it in half
so you can reveal the center.
Our golden
hand-cut fries there.
I'll split that burger
so that --
Wow!
Look at that.
There you are.
Cranberry
says "holiday."
Sage -- holiday.
Turkey and mayonnaise --
holiday.
That's right.
I mean, it just has
all those reminiscent flavors
that just bring it
back to you.
If you took your whole
Thanksgiving dinner,
wadded it up
into a ball,
and put a little crisp
on the outside of it,
that's what it tastes like.
Well, you guys got to come down
and try Easter here.
That's when he sticks
a hard-boiled egg that's colored
inside of the burger.
[ Laughs ]
Peter,
awesome job, man.
Christmas burger.
MAN: You know how, when you're
having Christmas dinner
and you try to get
that perfect balance
of, like, turkey and cranberry
and stuffing on your fork?
They achieve that
in this burger.
All that decadent
indulgence.
Decadent indulgence?
It is, yeah.
So, it should say
"The Ace --
the home of decadent
indulgence"?
There's only one Ace,
yep.
It's the place to be.
Ace is the place.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You guys don't have Thanksgiving
up here, do you?
We do, yeah.
You do have Thanksgiving?
Earlier than you guys.
What are you guys
giving thanks for?
Well, you know.
Being next to us?
[ Laughs ]
I'm just kidding.
[ Laughter ]
Don't want to hear that.