Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
You like to party?
...it's an old-world
throwdown.
I do like to party.
Why not?
Zicke zacke zicke zacke
hoi hoi hoi!
In Tacoma, Washington...
[ Polish accent ]
Freak-out deli. Five fingers.
...the mom-and-pop
European stop...
Things
are out of control!
...dressing up...
I don't think anybody's
ever wore a bow tie
in the history
of "Triple D."
...their take
on a comfort cure-all...
Do I have to go get
a hangover to try it?
Sure.
Okay.
In downtown Toronto...
Word to the ball.
...a restaurant
that's a shout-out...
[ Deep voice, echoing ]
Rodfather.
...to a classic
Italian favorite.
You're gonna have to pry this
out of my dead hands.
And in Syracuse, New York,
a family-run Polish joint...
That's really nice
comfort food.
...pouring on
the potato pancakes
with a heaping side
of pizzazz.
This is the first time
anybody's been
in snakeskin
kitchen pants.
Ohh, geez.
Yes, you foxy lady.
[ Giggles ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here in downtown Toronto,
Canada, on College Street,
right between Little Italy
and Little Portugal.
I'm here to check out a joint
with a chef
that's using fresh,
local ingredients and meats
to make these -- wait for it...
wait for it.
Exactly --
little round orbs of joy.
This is Hey Meatball.
♪ Hey, hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Hey! Hey! Hey, hey, hey! ♪
Curry balls and risotto.
Just the perfect amount
of spice.
Mac and cheese.
Just super flavorful.
Three meatballs.
It's perfect.
It fills you up.
It's really the only game in
town when it comes to meatballs.
FIERI: You call it
"Hey Meatball,"
you've got to be,
like, a meatball god.
[ Angelic chorus vocalizes ]
Were you raised
on meatballs?
Not at all.
FIERI: Actually,
it was a trip to Istanbul
that got the meatball rolling
for Chef Rod Bowers.
In Turkey, they have,
instead of hamburger shacks,
they have these little
kofta shacks.
Rod fell in love with
those Turkish meat delights
and brought the idea
back home to Canada.
I call myself
the "300-pound nonna."
Do you seriously?
"Home of the 300-pound nonna."
And he's backing up the nickname
with dishes like this...
Spaghetti
and meatballs.
...topped with an outrageous mix
of three meats.
The best thing to get
off the menu, I think.
Okay, let's get into this
meatball. First thing's up?
First thing up,
we're gonna make some balls.
Groovy.
Everything looks fine,
except what is that?
Is that a yolk?
That's
a firm-pressed yolk.
They usually come in
like that?
Yeah, man.
They come in, like,
bright and fresh and ready.
What are you feeding your
chickens up here in Canada?
Oranges, obviously.
So, we've got our mix
of our meats.
We grind
all of our own meat here.
A little bit
of fresh-ground chuck.
We got pork shoulder
and pork cheek.
And in we go.
And then I'm gonna add
this panada in here.
Panada is a mixture of any sort
of starch and a liquid.
One, you're incorporating
the moisture into the meatball,
and, two, we're gonna use that
as a binding agent.
Season with
a little bit of salt
and a little fresh-ground
pepper, chili paste.
And what kind of chili
is this?
This is serrano.
Really? That hot?
It's a little bit hot.
Then we're gonna
give it a mix.
[ Whirring ]
I'm gonna slowly add
mellow yellow here.
Fresh chopped garlic.
Turn it up a little bit.
[ Whirring intensifies ]
And then we sort of
take this out of here.
We'll like to let it chill
for a little bit, right?
Let it marry.
We'll put them on a straight
pan, add a little chicken stock.
We're gonna cook them
in a 500-degree oven
for about 20 minutes.
Word to the ball.
[ Clicks tongue ]
Where you getting
the pasta from?
We make it
at our other restaurant.
Shut the front door.
Seriously?
100% fresh pasta
in the water.
Salted?
Salted.
Then we're gonna ladle
a couple good --
Don't be shy.
War is over on the tomato sauce.
Some of our meatballs.
A little twang.
There you go.
Now the basil.
So, our pasta
goes straight in.
And that fresh pasta
will soak up sauce,
about a third more
than regular pasta.
And we just let it go in the pan
for another minute,
'cause we take it out
pretty al dente.
So, not too much
with the tongs.
It's not a castle. It should
not have a moat of sauce.
And then we're just gonna finish
with a little bit of --
Extra virgin --
the good stuff.
Add a little
local Parmesan.
Oh. It's gangster, man.
That is a mighty meatball.
If a sat there and squeezed
on this a little bit,
you'd actually find juice
coming out of it.
Wow.
I love the sauce,
because it's just really tomato
and it's really fresh.
The olive oil and basil
right at the end.
Ohh. Gonna have to pry this
out of my dead hands.
Awesome job, Chef.
Thanks, man.
It's just a classic dish --
nice, tender meatballs.
You can tell the noodles are
homemade. That's key for me.
I'm obsessed with it.
It's a take on fast food,
but it certainly
isn't made fast.
FIERI: It's kind of like
quick-served, slow food.
It's fast,
but you know you're getting,
like, the best-quality
ingredients.
FIERI: With a variety
keeping everyone happy,
he's got meatballs made
with just about everything --
pork, beef, chicken,
and even -- get this -- vegan.
But there's only one
that he's putting his name on.
We're gonna make
The Rodfather.
[ Dramatic Italian music plays ]
[ Record scratches ]
Hang on a second.
[ Deep voice, echoing ] Oh,
we are trying The Rodfather.
A mega meatball sandwich,
slathered with homemade pesto.
Well, let's see
your pesto process.
Let's do it right here.
So, I start
with fresh-peeled garlic,
and I put my walnuts in there
at the same time.
Very interesting. A great
alternative to pine nuts.
And I want to make a puree
with this.
Gonna put a little bit of salt
to break all of this down.
And the reason is, to do
this piece ahead of time
keeps you from doing it
when your basil's in
so you don't go beat your basil
to smithereens
and have nothing.
That's right.
♪ Hey! ♪
Bang it on.
And here I'm using
a neutral oil -- a canola.
Sometimes, when you use
olive oil in this process,
it can go bitter.
Okay.
And then I leave my basil
on the stem
till the last minute.
Okay.
And then
I'm gonna pulse this.
That's it.
I'm gonna add
grated Parmesan.
Parmesan
almost becomes...
The glue.
...the glue.
And then I loosen it
with really good stuff.
Extra virgin.
And that's it.
That's your pesto.
[ Smacks lips ] Oh.
[ Hoarsely ] Well, you didn't go
shy on the cheese.
No, man.
That's nice.
♪ Hey! ♪
Then we take the top
of our ciabatta bun
and dip it
in the beautiful fat
on top of the meatballs,
then right on the griddle.
So, we've made the bottom
of our bun nice and crispy.
Lots of holes in there.
This is our beautiful
bolognese.
And this bun is gonna
hold up to that sauce.
A couple of meatballs.
La-ta.
I'm gonna hit that
one more time.
Shredded cheese.
We take the top
of our ciabatta bun.
Here's where
the pesto comes in.
And this is kind of like
"Karate Kid" --
sort of,
"Wax on, wax off."
Ho-ho. One of my favorite combos
is pesto and tomato.
Look at this.
And look at that ciabatta.
That's a nice piece of bread
soaking that all up.
Go. Get into that.
Mmm. Mmm.
The meatballs are so
melt-in-your-mouth.
So you get the acid
of the tomato sauce
and a little bit of the
sweetness from cooking
down from the mirepoix.
So that's all happening.
The meatball itself
has its gentle, fat,
juicy moistness.
But it's that pesto
coming through over the top
that adds the brightness.
It adds that acid --
the sharp acid,
the fresh acid -- to it.
That's a really nice combo.
That's why
we call it The...
[ Deep voice, echoing ]
Rodfather!
It's The Rodfather.
[ Normal voice ]
It's incredibly good.
[ Deep voice, echoing ]
The Rodfather.
It's got everything
you can want.
I got to tell you.
I think that The...
[ Deep voice, echoing ]
Rodfather...
[ Normal voice ] was one
of the best I've had,
but we got to have more.
When we come back,
we're hanging out
at Hey Meatball
in Toronto, Canada.
What are we gonna have?
It's chicken meatball time,
baby!
FIERI: We're up north at
Hey Meatball in Toronto, Canada,
where Chef Rod Bowers
is using meatballs
in curry, burgers,
and his very own version
of winner, winner,
meatball chicken dinner.
Chicken balls!
I assume, from the ground
chicken that we have...
The chicken ball.
So, we're just gonna take
our ground thigh.
All thigh?
All thigh.
And we do use the drum
in this, as well.
You got to use dark meat.
100% organic, free-range.
A little
granulated garlic.
A little pinch of nutmeg,
fresh thyme.
A little bit of salt,
fresh pepper.
We're gonna bring this
to a slow stir.
And then we're gonna add
our mellow yellow.
Look at those.
Look at these.
Those aren't even
mellow yellow.
I've never seen -- I want to see
what chicken that is.
That's got to be
a red-headed chicken.
So, I'm gonna turn up the speed
just a little bit.
We're just gonna drizzle
this cream.
That's it.
And then we're just gonna add
a little bit of breadcrumbs.
There's so much moisture
in there
that this will work itself
together.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, so it soaks up
and gets that nice texture.
Then just slowly incorporate
those, and that's it.
We're gonna let this rest,
roll out our...
Roll out.
...little balls.
Okay.
And then --
Into the oven?
Into the oven.
What temp?
500 degrees.
Really?
Yeah.
Hot and fast. Build that crust.
How long?
They never take
more than 20 minutes.
Yeah, I was gonna say
20 would be about it.
Now we're into some gravy?
That's it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Cubes of butter.
[ High-pitched voice ] And what
we're gonna do is make a brew.
[ Normal voice ]
That's my Julia Child voice.
A little roux.
[ As Julia Child ]
As you take the chicken...
Same amount of flour
to butter.
[ Normal voice ]
Building a blond roux.
Get it to come together,
and it's there.
A little bit
of veggie stock.
We're gonna take it
to this slurry consistency,
then we're gonna add
our milk.
We're gonna add
a smashed clove of garlic,
bay leaf,
a little bit of salt.
And what "thyme" is it?
Love it.
The flour is starting
to thicken the cream.
Sautéed mushrooms.
Mmm! Baby creminis?
Yeah. Little creminis.
Exactly.
And that'd be the gravy.
Yep. That's the gravy
right there.
I like my mashed potatoes
soft, pillowy --
as the French say,
pomme puree.
Hey, look at that magic.
Chicken balls.
We'll just bring that over
to you there, brother.
Yeah. Sure.
Thank you very much.
Teamwork.
Look at that.
This is what our sauce
looks like --
just taking on a little bit
of the color of the shrooms.
And then this
is Sunday suppertime.
A little bit of olive oil.
And just for a tiny bit
of richness, some cheese.
There you go.
Okay, I don't --
You got to go spoon.
Fork or spoon?
Not necessary.
This is chicken-licious, man.
It's tender.
There's great texture to it.
Lots of really good mushroom.
Love the oil drizzle
and the pillow potatoes.
And the gravy is --
The cremini really makes it.
This is really,
really outrageous.
Go, man.
Excellent job.
Give it up for the man.
"The 300-pound,
bearded nonna."
Give your nonna a hug.
[ Chuckles ]
Coming up...
Whoa!
...we're headed
to Tacoma, Washington...
Very nice.
...for "The Chicken Dance"
and a soup...
That's our ingredients
for hangover soup.
...designed
with me in mind.
Why? Because by the time
you make the soup,
you won't even be
hung over anymore?
I'm here in Tacoma, Washington,
on a beautiful day,
right off the 512 Freeway
by Pacific Avenue,
to check out a joint
that, if you don't slow down
and take a look around,
you'll blow right by.
This is
Bruno's European Restaurant.
MAN: Cabbage rolls!
WOMAN: All of their food's
made from scratch.
It should be legal
to lick your plate here.
[ Chuckles ]
MAN: A lot of the food here,
I grew up with.
My dad was all Polish.
My mom was German. Love it.
FIERI:
These are stick-to-your-ribs
family recipes
that Polish Chef
Bruno Tomaszewski
imported when he came
to the States.
BRUNO:
Bruno's Schnitzel is ready!
FIERI: In 2011,
he and his wife, Christina,
opened this cozy café,
bringing old-school flair to
the front of the restaurant...
The Bruno's Schnitzel.
...and even a little
to the back...
I don't think anybody
has ever wore a bow tie
in the history of "Triple D."
I like the way you roll.
...dressed to impress,
and serving up a hearty
Polish remedy to what ails you.
Here is the hangover soup.
It's my favorite.
It has sausage, potatoes,
dill pickles --
just amazing flavors
in it.
Bruno, what are we
gonna make first?
Hangover soup?
Hangover.
Like, too much...
Vodka, or whatever.
[ Polish accent ] Vodka.
Whiskey.
[ Normal voice ]
Let's proceed. Whoa!
That's our ingredients
for hangover soup.
Why? Because by the time
you make the soup,
you won't even be
hung over anymore?
All right.
Get it started, boss.
Okay. So, first, water.
Got it.
Bacon.
Okay. Cooked bacon.
Just in
the simmering water.
Yes. Correct.
Cooked pork.
Okay.
Caramelized onions?
Yes.
Carrots. Celery.
Celery roots.
Sautéed mushrooms?
No, fried mushrooms.
Fried?
Yeah, because
it's better flavor.
Okay.
Next we add --
Sausage?
Yes.
Ah, I should try that.
[ Chuckles ]
Yep. It's sausage.
Really nice sausage
I got from Chicago.
I add salt, pepper,
allspice.
A lot of allspice
in Polish food?
Yes.
Bay leaf.
[ Whistles ]
Ground bay leaf.
Vegeta.
Oh, I know Vegeta.
All-purpose seasoning,
used a lot
in European-style cooking.
Paprika.
Hungarian paprika.
Yeah? A little spicy.
And Maggi.
Maggi -- kind of the Kitchen
Bouquet of Switzerland.
Yes, it's a browning,
richness type [Whistles ]
Diced potatoes. Leeks.
Leeks.
Crushed tomatoes.
Should call it
the Kitchen Sink Soup --
Everything is in this.
Okay. Next?
Pickles.
Good pickle. To the pot?
Yes.
Last thing, I'm gonna add
fresh garlic, fresh dill.
Heavy cream.
So, how much longer
till we taste it?
About a minute.
Do I have to go get a hangover
to try it?
Sure.
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
It's ready.
This is parsley --
fresh parsley.
Give it some green.
Mmm!
Rich with the potatoes.
The broth is thin,
not heavy.
The pork,
fresh vegetables...
Mmm!
Then the tang --
It has great tang.
Not a lot of heat,
but you definitely know
that there's spices in it.
You get a little bit
of that uniqueness
coming from
the pickle juice.
Mmm!
I think the pickle's
the real key there, buddy.
Excellent.
BRUNO: Hangover soup!
MAN: There's many times
I've needed it.
For cold-and-flu season?
Very nice. Very nice.
FIERI: Just remember -- around
here, the party doesn't stop.
Zicke zacke zicke zacke
hoi hoi hoi!
[ Humming "The Chicken Dance" ]
Quite often, we do
"The Chicken Dance" around here.
And if you don't know it,
you'll learn it.
WOMAN: It's just a small café,
and it's people
that really care
about their customers
and the food that they make,
and they just want
to feed people.
[ Polish folk music plays ]
Come on down to
Bruno's European Restaurant!
Things are
out of control!
[ Music continues ]
Up next, we're headed
to Syracuse, New York...
There's kind of a magic
that happens when you
walk in the door.
FIERI:
...for a family-run joint...
We'd probably move from Syracuse
if it weren't for this.
...dishing out real-deal,
old-school recipes.
Hungarian sauce!
I don't speak Polish.
I'm not deaf.
[ Laughing ]
Yes, I'm sorry.
You know, one of my favorite
parts of "Triple D"
is the family joints --
not just the joints
that families go to,
but the places
that are run by families.
So I'm here
in Syracuse, New York,
right on the city line
and about a mile and a half away
from the fairgrounds,
to check out a joint
that's run by a Polish family
that immigrated to the States
in '88.
This is Eva's.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Karolina, meat pierogi!
There's kind of a magic
that happens when you
walk in the door.
You feel like
you're in a piece of Europe.
Kopytka.
It's a love affair
with Polish food.
FIERI: And Eva Zaczynski
is the matchmaker,
with some help
from her daughter, Karolina,
and son, David.
It's just like
being in another world.
Kielbasa.
A lot like the Polish farm
Eva grew up on.
In 1997, she opened this joint
and brought that experience
to the locals.
Placki, golabkis,
kapusta.
Kielbasa.
So, what are we
gonna make?
We're gonna make
placki ziemniaczane.
Piero pancakes.
Potato pancakes!
Potato pancakes.
Okay.
Right now, it looks like
we're making potato applesauce.
All I'm seeing is mush.
They're gonna be good.
I'm telling you.
We've been
to a lot of places,
doing a lot
of different types of food,
but this is the first time
anybody's been
in snakeskin
kitchen pants.
Ohh, geez.
Yes, you foxy lady.
[ Giggles ]
You like to party?
I do like to party.
Why not?
Onion.
All of this
for the pancake?
Yes.
An egg
to work as binder.
Yep.
A little pepper.
A little seasoning.
And a little spices. Yeah.
A little salt.
A bit of flour.
All that comes together?
We're all set.
All right.
What are we making now?
We're making
Hungarian sauce.
Who?
Hungarian sauce!
I don't speak Polish.
I'm not deaf.
[ Laughing ]
Yes, I'm sorry.
"Hungarian sauce!"
[ Laughing ]
Now we're gonna add
the ground beef.
Okay.
So, now the meat's brown.
Then we're gonna put it
in the pot.
Then we're gonna put
a little bit of oil,
and then we're gonna
put onion,
peppers,
and the garlic.
Now we're gonna put
the fried peppers,
with the onion and garlic,
to the ground beef.
Next we're gonna do
diced tomato.
Tomato puree.
Mix it a little bit.
So, then you're gonna
put paprika...
cayenne...
Chili flake.
Pepper, salt,
some spices.
Okay, so, how long
is this gonna cook?
An hour.
And then
we're gonna put that
over the top
of the potato pancakes?
Yes.
Put some oil on.
[ Sizzling ]
Oh, there we go!
That's two.
Flip them?
One moment. Yes.
Oh, look at that!
They're beautiful.
I know.
And that's one order
right there?
Only one order.
[ Whistles ]
A little sour cream
on top of that?
Yes.
Mmm. Wow!
That's really nice
comfort food.
Mmm!
Potato pancake --
nice, little crisp outside,
tender on the inside.
And then this gravy got
a little bit of spice to it.
That is great.
Thank you.
Mmm!
Hungarian placki,
honey.
Oh, that looks great.
WOMAN: I love to order these
during the winter
or, like, when it starts
to be falltime.
Oh, they're so good.
Just all great -- the fresh
food, the presentation.
But that's it.
It's the real deal.
This is Easter.
This is Christmas.
This is everything
rolled up into one.
We'd probably move from Syracuse
if it weren't for this.
Really?
So, that's it for this
flavor-town road trip.
But don't you worry --
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Singing folk song in Polish ]
Zicke zacke zicke zacke
hoi hoi hoi!