Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Drop it like it...
...it's a mom-and-pop
one-stop shop.
Whoo!
In Chatham, New Jersey...
This is like culinary
Disneyland, and this is Goofy.
Hello!
...an old buddy...
Look at that.
[ Whistles ]
...firing up
real-deal Italian...
America's finest.
...with his way better half.
We're gonna go on the crispy
chicken and the penne vodka now.
Whatever you want, honey.
FIERI:
And in Olympia, Washington...
Here you go --
the Oysters Creole.
Philosophy and cooking
go hand in hand.
...the funky breakfast,
lunch, and dinner joint...
Can you say that
three times fast?
No.
Very nice.
...spreading the love...
You're going wild
on this.
...with the bounty
of the county.
I'd come back to Olympia
for that.
We'll take ya.
That's all right here right now
on "DDD."
So, I'm here
in Chatham, New Jersey,
about 35 miles west
of New York City.
Now, I've been cooking
with Carl Ruiz for years --
awesome chef.
And I've been telling him,
"You got to open
your own joint."
Finally, he and his wife
took my advice
and opened their own place.
And they were smart --
they named it after her.
This is Marie's
Italian Specialties.
This is like sitting
in my mother's kitchen.
The food is like you would get
in a little trattoria in Rome.
On a scale of 1 to 10,
I would give this place a 15.
FIERI: Makes sense.
Carl's one of the craziest
chefs I know.
Easy, easy!
And Marie's been cranking out
killer Italian food
all her life.
What makes your
Italian food different?
It's just
simple Italian food,
but we do it
with the best ingredients.
FIERI:
And a little sideshow.
Today we're gonna --
Aah!
Don't make me nuts.
I have a family.
This is like culinary
Disneyland, and this is Goofy.
Hello!
But there's nothing funny
about Marie's Italian chicken.
Baked and fried chicken
at the same time.
It's like getting punched
and kicked by a karate ninja.
Let's get
that mac and cheese up.
Served with a side
of cheesy heaven.
The best macaroni and cheese
I've ever had in my life.
What we're gonna do is we're
just gonna brine this chicken.
It's a simple salt brine.
It smells already brined.
What?
It smells brined.
[ Both laugh ]
We put water in it,
and then just salt.
What?
Are you Harry Potter?
Whoo!
So, I stir this up.
I leave it in the fridge
for a couple hours,
and then it's ready
to go.
I make the spice rub,
which is garlic powder,
Italian seasoning,
a little kosher salt.
Mix that together.
Take the chickens out.
Olive oil
with red wine vinegar.
The spice rub.
That's it.
Simple. Magic.
Now what do we do with it?
I cover it with aluminum.
I put it in the oven.
At what temp?
400.
How long?
45 minutes.
Next up.
Making mac and cheese.
Start with little shells.
American cheese --
America's finest.
Shred mozz,
parmigiano-reggiano.
We need a binder,
obviously.
So we use
a parmesan cream.
I eat this when I'm depressed
by myself.
Top it
with a little parmesan cheese.
That goes here.
A little fried prosciutto.
Mmm, that's good.
Goes in the oven.
How long's that gonna bake?
About 20 minutes --
it goes pretty quick.
Look at this.
Do we let it cool?
No.
You take it hot and drop it
in the fryer?
Drop it like it's hot.
Drop it like it...
[ Both laugh ]
Chicken's ready.
Mac and cheese is ready?
Mac and cheese is ready.
[ Whistles ]
See? Crispy.
Look at that.
Steaming hot.
Here's what he's done --
brines it, roasts it,
so now you've got all
that superflavored chicken,
and then takes it and drops it
in the deep fryer.
And I'm gonna
tell you something --
I don't know
that I can recommend
that you eat more than one
of these a month, but tasty.
Mmm.
There you go. Look at this.
Not many times I've had
mac and cheese
that the ratio of the cheese
outweighs the mac two to one.
That's cheesy.
Chicken ready.
[ Gobbles ]
The chicken is perfect.
It's so juicy on the inside.
The skin is really crispy.
And the mac and cheese
is all good.
The greatest comfort food
I've ever eaten -- ever.
What's up, Holmes?
How are you doing?
Carl always comes over to talk,
and Marie does the same.
They're like friends next door.
They're just nice, kind, fun.
It's just like home.
You know you're guaranteed
a great meal.
FIERI: Whether it's chicken parm
on a baguette,
mussels sautéed in marinara,
or a sweet, salty sandwich
stuffed with Italian pork.
MARIE: Sacred Swine.
Amazing. Just amazing.
A complete dinner on a sandwich.
We're making
the Sacred Swine sandwich.
Fire it up.
Pork shoulder.
Tee-hee-hee!
[ Howls ]
Garlic powder.
So, we're not diluting this
into the water first?
Nah.
Okay.
Out the window with
those cooking principles.
Silly principles.
Salt, bay leaves.
Next...
Bucket full of water.
And how long
are we gonna let this brine?
This has to be overnight.
♪ Row, row, row your pig ♪
So, now we got
the brined pork.
Now it's all brined.
Now we're gonna get ready
to roast.
A little bit of water.
And a little olive oil.
Red wine vinegar
and spice rub.
Granulated garlic, the Italian
seasoning, and the salt.
The best way to cook this --
overnight, low and slow.
Look at that.
[ Whistles ]
Can I try this?
Awesome.
Thank you.
That's old-school
delicious Italian pork.
Now what do we do?
Take this off.
You shred it all up
into its own juice.
Now the broccoli rabe?
Yep.
Olive oil, garlic.
Drop your broccoli rabe.
Kosher salt.
Why broccoli rabe?
Broccoli rabe,
it's on the sour side,
and when you roast pork
for a long time,
it becomes
very, very sweet.
So it's kind of
a sweet and sour
but in the most natural,
subtle way possible.
Bread.
Isn't that good?
I love that.
Smell the rye.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, first up.
Put a little polenta.
The polenta is gonna work
as one of the creams
to this sandwich.
We're adding the moisture.
Right.
Nice.
Broccoli rabe.
Whoa! Putting a whole garden
in there, huh?
Oh, it's a good sandwich.
A little pulled pork.
Next?
Vodka sauce.
That you make
yourself also.
Yes.
A little reggiano.
Then you gingerly cut it.
And there it is.
Here's what you got --
the bread's outstanding.
The creamy polenta is like
mayonnaise with a cause.
The pork, super tender.
The sweetness
coming through it.
But you know
what the real kicker
to this whole sandwich is?
That broccoli rabe.
It's got that sharpness,
a little bit garlic
coming through real strong.
The broccoli rabe
is what makes the sandwich.
That's great.
Outstanding.
[ Laughs ]
Table eight!
It's sort of like
an Italian pillow,
with that polenta
and the soft bread.
MAN:
It's a unique sandwich.
It's not too garlicky,
it's not too oily.
It's just perfect.
It's cooked perfectly.
I would fill
an entire Jacuzzi with this
and just sit right in it.
So, here's the deal.
Hanging out
with one of my best friends,
cooking outrageous food
at Marie's Italian Specialties.
When we come back,
on "DDD,"
his wife, Marie, the boss,
is gonna come back
and make what?
Whatever she wants.
Exactly. We'll see you
in a little bit.
FIERI:
At Marie's Italian Specialties
in Chatham, New Jersey,
cooking with my buddy Carl
was just the appetizer.
Now I get to work with the real
brains of this operation...
We're gonna go on the crispy
chicken and the penne vodka now.
Whatever you want, honey.
FIERI:
...his wife, Marie.
Marie is the biggest
hidden secret you ever met.
FIERI: Okay, what are you
gonna make me?
Okay, we're gonna make
the risotto for the arancini.
Okay, the arancini.
Arancini.
They're rice balls, okay?
Different styles
of making them.
This is
gonna be interesting.
That's hot, so we're just
gonna take arborio rice.
And we're gonna
toast it first.
Okay, so now it's toasted
up to the color we want.
So, we add one quart
of salted water.
We don't want it
to get really mushy.
Normally, with risotto,
it's very, very creamy.
We want it to almost have
the same texture as rice.
Now we're gonna make
the tomato sauce.
Extra virgin olive oil,
pureed garlic.
And then we're gonna add
tomato sauce.
Dry basil,
granulated garlic.
Copious amount. Wow!
And just
a little bit of salt.
This is old-school,
leave-it-on-the-stove,
cook-it-for-awhile sauce.
Exactly.
And we get it going
for about an hour,
and then we put
our raw meatballs in.
This has got the --
Ground beef,
granulated garlic and basil,
parmesan cheese,
bread crumbs, salt.
So, they'll cook
inside the sauce?
They cook in the sauce.
Okay, we're gonna make
rice balls.
Give me a rundown.
So, we're gonna start
with our homemade meatballs.
The meatballs that we cooked
in the sauce.
The parmesan cheese,
dried parsley,
granulated garlic,
six large eggs,
shredded mozzarella,
and seasoned bread crumbs.
Now we're gonna add
the rice.
We're gonna fluff it up
a little bit.
Then we're gonna add
our salt,
some of the tomato sauce,
give it a final mix.
And now you start to form
the arancini.
Exactly.
Just a little coating
of some bread crumbs.
A lot of times,
people see arancini
where they'll put the filling
in the center,
wrap the rice around it.
This is an all-encompassing,
every-bite-you're-a-winner.
Right. Exactly.
350.
3½ minutes.
That's it?
That's it.
[ Whistles ] Some of
the homemade tomato sauce.
Dig in.
Look at that --
nice and tender,
cheese coming through.
And I can already hear
the crunch just from the fork.
The texture's outrageous.
I like the little bit
of the meatball in there.
Tomato sauce
is outstanding.
But the crunch on the outside --
crunchy and then creamy.
[ Laughs ]
It's killer.
That right there
rocks the house.
Thank you.
You're the bomb.
All right,
here's the rice balls.
WOMAN:
They're out of this world --
all kinds of goodies
on the inside.
If you've never had an arancini
ball, you must try it.
You got to come check
this joint out -- real deal.
And this guy...
FIERI: Up next...
I don't know
what you're gonna do!
I'm going
to make a mustache.
...we're headed
to Olympia, Washington...
I don't know why I have become
your sous-chef for this.
I don't mind it a bit.
...for oysters gone wild...
That'll do her.
...and a hash extravaganza.
You have got to love
the great northwest.
I'm here in downtown
Olympia, Washington,
about a mile away
from the state capitol.
Now, we're gonna check out
a joint that's doing it all --
breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
Oh, vegetarian, vegan,
and meat eaters alike.
This is Darby's Café.
I'm gonna get chicken going
for the CBS.
All walks of life,
they all come here to Darby's.
FIERI:
All looking for the same thing.
Good old-fashioned cooking.
Like a mom-and-pop home diner.
FIERI:
Oh, I like that.
This joint is actually
chapter two
for Nate Reilly
and his wife, Sara.
I was an insurance agent,
and Nate was a manager.
I managed a video store.
FIERI: In '05,
they took the plunge,
bought this existing restaurant,
and got creative.
We have great cooks that
collaborate with us on recipes.
Including head chef
Johanna Vasseur.
Hash is great,
the scrambles are great.
Local vegetable, local fruit.
FIERI: Not to mention
dynamite seafood...
JOHANNA:
About 30 seconds on the oysters.
FIERI: ...that ends up
on Darby's version
of the eggs Benedict.
We're gonna make
a Creole cream sauce
for the
Creole Oysters Benedict today.
Can you say that
three times fast?
No.
Very nice.
We're gonna melt
some butter here.
So, once that's melted,
we're adding flour.
All-purpose?
Yep.
We're gonna go ahead
and add milk.
So we're making a béchamel.
Did you go
to culinary school?
No, sir. I have a degree
in philosophy.
Philosophy and cooking
go hand in hand.
Exactly, right?
White vinegar --
add a little tang.
We'll let this thicken up
for a little while.
We're gonna go ahead
and add our spices --
paprika, kosher salt,
ground clove, nutmeg,
a little oregano.
There you go.
Wish I could hire you.
Cayenne, garlic powder.
Onion powder.
I'm gonna let this thicken
for about 20 minutes.
All right,
what are we making?
Seasoned flour dredge
for the oysters.
All-purpose flour,
onion powder, black pepper.
Granulated?
Garlic.
Pap.
Chili.
You smell that?
How do you know?
Come on now.
Salt.
Incorporate
till it's all up in there.
Oysters.
[ Whistles ]
Dredge. [ Laughs ]
We're gonna take
our fresh Pacific oysters.
We're gonna stick them
in here first.
Give them
a little egg bath.
With buttermilk, yep.
Oh, with buttermilk.
Then back into the flour.
Do you let that batter just
crustify up on that oyster?
"Crustifarian."
[ Laughs ]
And now they're gonna go
in the fryer.
We've got our home fries.
Toasted English muffin.
Grilled red pepper rings.
Oysters --
two per muffin.
Couple poached eggs.
Okay, this is
the Creole cream sauce.
Thank you.
That's it.
Mmm!
We're talking about super,
super fresh oysters,
a nice dredge.
Awesome sauce.
There's good spice.
There's great crunch.
With the roasted
red bell pepper,
the home fries,
once you pile that together...
I'd come back to Olympia
for that.
We'll take ya.
All right, Ray, here you go --
the Oysters Creole.
That's amazing.
It's got a nice kick to it.
It's got a nice little spice
to it.
These guys do it right.
They do everything right.
All right, we've got
our winter squash hash.
With squash and apples and
sausage and cranberry compote.
Absolutely lovely.
FIERI:
What are we making now?
Cranberry chutney for the winter
squash and apple hash.
Fresh cranberries,
water to cover.
And let them simmer
until they pop a little bit.
What do we have here?
Ginger?
Very good.
Garlic.
Nice.
You're going wild on this.
Sweet and savory.
Lemon zest.
Sugar, salt.
Can we put off to the side
and let it cook?
We'll let this go
for another 20 minutes.
Let them turn into
like a nice smooth sauce.
And on to the...?
Sausage.
This is local ground pork.
Rosemary?
That's right.
[ Whistles ] Sage.
Fennel.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Garlic.
I don't know why I have become
your sous-chef for this.
I don't mind it a bit.
Wow. Nice squash.
Thank you. [ Laughs ]
We need that.
Did you think
I was gonna eat it?
I don't know
what you're gonna do!
I'm going to make
a mustache.
All right,
we're just gonna chop her up.
Just scoop out the seeds,
chop it.
Do a little oil.
Do do do.
How long's it gonna go?
About a half hour
at 400 degrees.
Here's our
seasoned pork sausage.
We're gonna cook that up.
Break it down
a little bit more, though.
Whoo!
Got green pepper, onion,
red pepper.
Give that a little mix.
And then we're gonna do
our squash.
Just about yea much.
And a Granny Smith apple.
Love this.
Just let that go for about
a couple more minutes
till it browns up nice.
We spoon in
our cranberry chutney.
Slip on some eggs.
Ooh, and you got them
runny upstairs.
Our homemade biscuit.
Make biscuits as well?
Every morning.
The apple's still got
some crunch to it.
The squash is nutty.
It's nice to get the acid
of the cranberry.
It reminds me of stuffing
at Thanksgiving.
Yeah, that's what
we're going for.
That's pure.
WOMAN: Squash hash.
Oh, it's so good.
It's a little sweet,
a little spicy.
It's delish.
[ Laughs ]
You got anything else
up your sleeve?
We'll do a blueberry
crunch roller.
When we get back.
We're hanging out here
in Olympia.
This girl's on fire.
Not literally, but you get...
Welcome back to Darby's Café
in Olympia, Washington.
They're creative.
They're fun.
Yeah!
They're funky.
Blueberry roller up!
It's a tortilla.
Bowl of granola
and fresh blueberries.
Tastes healthy even though
it's full of ice cream.
FIERI:
So, what are we making?
Maple bourbon granola
for our blueberry crunch roller.
Bourbon.
Did you put enough in?
Mine will just have --
little bit more.
Very nice.
That'll do her.
Okay.
[ Laughs ]
Oil, real maple syrup --
real stuff --
and vanilla extract.
We're just gonna whisk
this together.
Now we'll ask everybody else
to come to the party here.
We got oats.
Sliced almonds, pecans,
and salt.
And we're just gonna spread this
on a sheet pan.
Let's get it done.
Cook this off
in the oven for...?
About half an hour.
Okay.
Mmm, that is good.
We're gonna roll up
the blueberry crunch roller.
Do it before I eat
all the granola.
We start with a tortilla.
We're gonna warm this up just
a little bit so it's pliable.
Looking good. Cream cheese
frosting. Blueberries.
Good-looking blueberries.
Yeah, they're great.
And our maple bourbon granola.
Let's roll it up.
Nice, tight roll.
Gonna stab it in the middle
and put it in the fryer,
get it crispy.
We're gonna
deep-fry this?
We're gonna deep-fry it.
Oh, my son Hunter
would love this.
Have a scoop
of vanilla ice cream.
I thought this was a healthy
joint at Darby's Café.
It's got calcium.
Got a point there.
Roller coming out!
Look at this.
It's like a egg roll
of the week at Tex Wasabi's.
Wait, buh-buh-buh-buh!
We're gonna do a little bit
more granola on top.
A little blueberry,
a little pow-pow.
A little pow-pow.
All right, get in there.
Might be a little hot.
It's gonna burn,
burn, burn, burn.
Oh, God.
Mmm.
Oh, my gosh.
The blueberries
are so super fresh.
It's warm, it's crunchy,
it's comforting.
I wouldn't change a thing.
That's really good.
Hunter, you would
love this, dude.
Two blueberry rollers.
It's a really good breakfast,
but it can be a dessert, too.
WOMAN:
This is amazing.
It's totally healthy
with the granola, right?
As you walk down the streets,
go by Darby's Café...
This is who you get.
You're the bomb.
Thank you.
Dot com.
Check it out.
So that's it for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
You can't get
these apart?
Can't get them apart.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, I'll get them
apart now.
No, you won't.
Want to bet?
I got like eight bucks.
Eight bucks.
I told ya.
It doesn't come apart.
Wow!
Marie,
can I borrow eight bucks?
[ Laughter ]
Psycho.