HEY, EVERYBODY! I'M GUY FIERI,
AND WE'RE ROLLING OUT,
LOOKING FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS, AND DIVES.
(Fieri) THIS TRIP...
WHO'S IN CHARGE?
(whooshing)
...WE'RE MEETING UP
WITH SOME MATCHES
MADE IN FLAVORTOWN HEAVEN.
YOU'RE GONNA GET ME RUN
OUT OF TOWN, MAN.
IN FORT GREENE, BROOKLYN...
SITTING ON A PORCH,
HAVING THE SAME DREAM.
...THE BARBECUE JOINT...
THAT BONE IS BIGGER
THAN YOU!
MM-HMM.
...SMOKING UP
SOME SERIOUS NYC 'CUE.
MM-AHH!
THAT'S A GOOD NOISE
RIGHT THERE.
I LIKE THAT.
(laughs)
AND IN MANTEO,
NORTH CAROLINA...
HOLY MOLEY!
...THE TEX-MEX SPOT...
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
WHERE A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE
TEAM...
DOING GOOD. COME ON, MAN!
YOU CAN DO IT!
LET'S HEAR IT FOR HIM,
EVERYBODY!
(applause)
...ARE GOING TOE-TO-TOE...
I UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE'S A LITTLE COMPETITION
THAT GOES ON
BETWEEN THE TWO OF YOU.
...IN THE KITCHEN.
(Austrian accent)
YOU CAN DO IT, ROCKY.
YOU ONLY GOT
FOUR MORE ROUNDS TO GO.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS, & DIVES."
I'M HERE IN THE FORT GREENE
NEIGHBORHOOD OF BROOKLYN
RIGHT DOWN THE STREET FROM
WHERE THE BROOKLYN NETS PLAY
TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
THAT DOES...
OH, IT'S REALLY GOOD, TOO.
IT'S NOT MEATBALL.
IT'S NOT EGG ROLLS.
(record scratches)
OH! BARBECUE!
THAT'S WHY IT'S CALLED
THE SMOKE JOINT.
THE SMOKE JOINT
IS THE PLACE TO BE.
SHORT RIBS!
MOUTH-WATERING, SUCCULENT,
FALLING-OFF-THE-BONE...
HALF-CHICKEN, SIDE SLAW.
EVERYBODY -- WHEN YOU SAY,
"I'M GOING TO THE SMOKE JOINT,"
THEY'RE LIKE, "OOH."
THAT'S MUSIC TO THE EARS
OF OWNERS CRAIG SAMUEL...
SPARE RIB AND A BROOKLYN WING
COMING UP NEXT.
...AND BEN GROSSMAN...
CHICKEN SANDWICH UP.
(Fieri)
WHO'S IN CHARGE?
(whooshing)
...TWO BUDDIES WHO FIRST
MASTERED FRENCH CUISINE,
THEN WENT WHOLE HOG
IN ANOTHER DIRECTION.
(Grossman)
WE'RE BARBECUING ON THE DECK,
AND HIS WIFE, LAURA,
IS LIKE,
"IDIOTS, THERE'S NOT MUCH
GOOD BARBECUE IN THE CITY."
AND HAD YOU WORKED
IN BARBECUE BEFORE THEN?
NO, NO.
I ATE A LOT OF IT.
AWESOME STRATEGY.
PAIR THAT WITH 2 1/2 YEARS
OF RECIPE TESTING,
AND THEY'RE CRANKING OUT
BARBECUE CLASSICS,
LIKE PULLED-PORK SANDWICHES,
SPICY PORK HOT LINKS,
AND THIS NUMBER-ONE SELLER...
BEEF RIBS.
...A BRONTOSAURUS-SIZED PLATTER
THAT WOULD MAKE
FRED FLINTSTONE BLUSH!
IT IS ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S START
WITH THE BARBECUE SAUCE.
LET ME LET YOU GO.
OH. ALL RIGHT.
WE START OFF WITH KETCHUP.
THAT'S THE BASE,
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THE FOUNDATION
OF THE FANTASTICNESS?
FOLLOW IT UP
WITH SOME DARK BROWN SUGAR.
(pounding rhythmically)
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
OKAY.
WOW.
LOOK AT THE CASCADING POUR.
GIVES IT A LITTLE TARTNESS.
DOES THAT CHANGE THE FLAVOR?
THAT HELPS.
WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
THERE YOU GO.
SOY SAUCE.
I LOVE
THE CASCADING POUR, DUDE.
MOLASSES.
YOU WANT TO DO THIS?
I WANT TO SEE IT.
WELL, I'LL MAKE THE NOISE.
READY?
(laughs)
OKAY, HERE WE GO.
(pops lips)
(laughs)
SOME CAYENNE PEPPER
FOR SPICE.
VERY NICE.
CHILI POWDER
GIVES IT DEPTH.
LOOK AT YOU WITH
ALL THE DESCRIPTOR POINTS!
THAT'S PUREED CHIPOTLES?
YES.
IT'S GONNA HAVE
A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
YES.
YOU TURN THAT ON.
YOU GET OUT YOUR MONSTER WHISK,
WHISK THAT TOGETHER.
OKAY. SO, MIX THIS UP.
LET IT SIMMER.
HOW LONG IS THIS
GONNA SIMMER?
BETWEEN
THREE AND FOUR HOURS.
THEY BETTER BE
SOME BOMB SHORT RIBS.
MAKE ME DO ALL THIS WORK
OVER HERE.
FREE LABOR.
YEAH, ISN'T THAT GREAT?
OKAY.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING NEXT?
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE MAKING A SPICE RUB
FOR OUR BEEF SHORT RIBS.
WE START OFF
WITH GRANULATED SUGAR.
BUTCHER-GROUND
BLACK PEPPER.
WE LIKE IT
NICELY, COARSELY GROUND.
KOSHER SALT.
DARK BROWN SUGAR.
IT GIVES IT
A DEPTH OF FLAVOR.
REGULAR SUGAR THAT'S BEEN
FORTIFIED WITH MOLASSES.
THAT'S WHERE THEY MAKE THIS --
THE BROWN.
THAT'S
WHERE THE COLOR COMES IN.
THIS GUY KNOWS
WHAT HE'S TALKING ABOUT.
AND WE FINISH IT UP WITH
SOME CAYENNE PEPPER FOR HEAT.
(whistles)
MIX IT TOGETHER.
RUB SOME IN YOUR EYE.
MIX IT WITH MY HAND.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THEN THE SHORT RIBS
ARE COMING FROM WHERE?
SHORT RIBS
COME FROM COLORADO.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THIS IS TOGETHER?
GET THE SHORT RIBS.
YEP.
LITTLE FAT CAP ON THERE.
YOU WANT TO LEAVE THAT
ON THERE
BECAUSE IT JUST BASTES THE MEAT
AS IT GOES.
SO, YOU WANT
TO RUB THIS DOWN
WITH SOME OF THAT SPICE RUB
WE JUST MADE.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
THINK THAT YOU'RE RUBBING
IT INTO THE MEAT.
BUT ACTUALLY,
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO
IS GET A NICE, LIBERAL,
AND EVEN COAT.
FLIP IT OVER.
SO, LET THIS GO
6, 8, 12, 24 HOURS,
WHATEVER YOU CAN GET
OUT OF IT.
ABSOLUTELY.
WHAT ARE
WE GONNA SMOKE IT WITH?
WHAT KIND OF WOOD?
WE'RE GONNA SMOKE THAT
WITH HICKORY.
HICKORY.
DICKORY.
DOCK.
THANK YOU.
BRING THE RIBS.
(chimes ring)
THERE YOU GO.
THAT'S THE MAGIC,
RIGHT THERE.
WHERE DID YOU GO, CRAIG?
WHOOF!
ALL RIGHT.
YOU CUT IT IN HALF.
ONE HALF IS ONE PORTION?
TWO BIG, FAT RIBS?
ONE HALF IS ONE PORTION.
(whistles)
HOLY BRONTOSAURUS RIB!
ALL RIGHT.
TAKE THIS OVER TO THE GRILL.
GONNA BRUSH IT JUST A LITTLE BIT
WITH THE JOINT SMOKE --
IT'S GONNA KISS IT.
LITTLE LOVE
ON THE GRILL.
LET IT CARAMELIZE
SOME OF THAT SAUCE.
JUST FOR A SECOND.
AND ONE MORE BRUSH
BEFORE IT GOES OUT.
THERE YOU GO.
WHOA!
THAT'S PULL-APART TENDER
RIGHT THERE.
SUPER TENDER,
FLAKY, FALL-APARTY.
MM-AHH!
THAT'S A GOOD NOISE
RIGHT THERE.
I LIKE THAT.
(laughs)
THAT'S SUPER TENDER.
YOU JUST MOP IT UP
WITH SOME OF ITS OWN SAUCE.
THE FAT
HAS JUST MELTED INTO IT.
IT IS SO RICH
WITH THE SMOKE, THE BONE,
THE NATURAL FAT,
THE DRY RUB.
DUDE, I'M NOT KIDDING YOU.
THAT IS OUT OF BOUNDS.
OUT-OF-BOUNDS KILLER.
MMM! CRAZY GOOD!
THAT'S ONE OF THE BEST BARBECUE
THINGS I'VE EVER HAD.
I AM TASTING HEAVEN.
THAT'S THE PICTURE.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I WANT
TO COME AND SEE.
THAT BONE IS BIGGER
THAN YOU!
MM-HMM.
THE BIGGEST, MOST BODACIOUS
THING ON THE MENU.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK...
...WE'RE GOING SOUTH
TO NORTH...
HOLLA.
...WITH A BIG-CITY BOROUGH'S
TAKE...
BROOKLYN WINGS UP.
...ON AN UPSTATE STANDARD.
THE FLAVOR JETS
JUST TURNED ON.
(coughs)
LITTLE SPICY.
TRIPLE D IS HANGING
AT THE SMOKE JOINT
IN FORT GREENE, BROOKLYN,
WHERE OWNERS CRAIG SAMUEL
AND BEN GROSSMAN
HAVE COOKED UP A MENU
TAPPING INTO ALL REALMS
OF THE BARBECUE KINGDOM.
I LOVE THE FACT
THAT IT IS NEW YORK,
BUT IT FEELS LIKE
YOU'RE IN BARBECUE CITY.
(man)
THIS IS REAL NEW YORK BARBECUE.
TRANSLATION -- A MELTING POT,
JUST LIKE THE BIG APPLE ITSELF.
(Samuel) WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA FIND HERE
IS A BUNCH
OF DIFFERENT STYLES
COMING TOGETHER
UNDER ONE ROOF.
SOUTHERN FROM NORTH CAROLINA,
MEMPHIS, TEXAS RIBS.
THEY'RE EVEN TAKING A PAGE
FROM UPSTATE NEW YORK
WITH A FUNKIFIED VERSION
OF THE BUFFALO WING...
BUFFALO WINGS UP.
THEY'RE NICE AND TENDER,
JUICY.
...TOPPED OFF WITH A SAUCE
THAT'S GOT AS MUCH FLAVOR
AS NEW YORK'S BIGGEST BOROUGH.
WE'RE MAKING
OUR HOLLAPENO SAUCE --
H-O-L-L-A-P-E-N-O.
HOLLA?
LIKE "HOLLABACK GIRL."
HOLLA.
SO, WE START THAT OFF
BY PUREEING TOGETHER
SOME CHIPOTLES
AND SOME SAMBAL.
LIKE,
THIS IS GONNA BE HOT.
IT'S GONNA MAKE YOU...
HOLLA.
HERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT.
WE GET
OUR INDUSTRIAL-SIZED BUCKET.
STARTING OFF
WITH SOME HOT SAUCE.
AFTER THAT,
WE PUT IN THIS SPICE MIX.
SAMBAL AND CHIPOTLE.
AND THAT
JUST SMOOTHES IT OUT.
FOLLOW IT UP
WITH MOLASSES.
NICE.
LITTLE BIT OF HONEY.
DONE.
BROWN SUGAR.
WHITE SUGAR.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR.
THERE WE GO.
YOU
AND YOUR CASCADING POURS.
(chuckles)
DISTILLED WHITE VINEGAR.
WHITE VINEGAR.
THERE YOU GO.
DIDN'T THAT FEEL GOOD?
JUST LET IT OUT.
AND WORCESTERSHIRE SAUCE.
GIVE THAT A STIR.
AND YOU REALLY JUST WANT
TO LET THIS SIT
FOR A FEW HOURS.
LET ALL THOSE FLAVORS
DEVELOP.
AND YOU'RE READY
TO GO.
THAT'S
OUR SPICY BARBECUE SAUCE.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
POUR SOME OF THAT
IN MY POCKET.
(laughs)
OKAY.
DRY RUB TIME.
YES, SIR.
HIT IT.
ALL RIGHT. SO, WE'RE MAKING
OUR 77 SPICE RUB.
SPANISH PAPRIKA.
KOSHER SALT.
GRANULATED GARLIC.
CUMIN.
OOH, CUMIN.
BETTER WATCH OUT.
PEPPER.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MUSTARD.
ONION.
YOU GOT IT.
CHILI POWDER.
WHAT ARE WE,
A SPICE MARKET RIGHT NOW?
CAYENNE POWDER.
AND SUGAR.
AND I ACTUALLY LIKE
TO MIX THIS BY HAND.
MM, 'CAUSE BY FOOT'S ODD.
(strained) THANK YOU.
WOW.
RIGHT UP THE NOSE.
SO, WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD
AND RUB THESE WINGS
WITH OUR 77 SPICE.
RUB THEM.
ARE WE GONNA SMOKE THESE?
YES, SIR.
WITH THE HICKORY?
WITH HICKORY.
HOW LONG?
THESE
FOR ABOUT 2 1/2 HOURS.
2 1/2 HOURS.
RENDERED DOWN.
THEY'LL BE FINISHED, AND THEN
FINISH THEM BY FRYING THEM?
DROP THEM
IN THE DEEP FRYER.
BOOM.
THERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT.
SO, WE USE A LITTLE BIT
OF THE HOLLA SAUCE
AND A LITTLE BIT
OF THE JOINT SMOKE SAUCE.
GIVE IT A GOOD TOSS.
THE FLAVOR JETS
JUST TURNED ON.
AND WE SERVE THAT
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF...
...BLUE CHEESE DRESSING.
(coughs)
LITTLE SPICY.
MMM.
LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE.
NOT TOO MUCH.
I STILL WANT THEM
TO BE HOT WINGS.
THE SAUCE IS KILLER.
IT'S GOT ENOUGH HEAT
TO MAKE YOU HOLLA,
AND THEN IT'S GOT
JUST ENOUGH SWEET
TO BRING YOU BACK AROUND.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
THAT YOU NEED BLUE CHEESE.
KILLER.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
EXCELLENT.
(man) I USUALLY HAVE TO WIPE
MY WHOLE FACE OFF.
YOU KNOW, WHEN I'M REALLY
HUNGRY, I CAN EAT ABOUT 40, 45.
IT'S LIKE A 10 OUT OF 10.
EVERY TIME I COME,
IT'S JUST SUCH A GREAT TREAT.
YOU GUYS REALLY PUT
YOUR HEART INTO IT.
THAT WAS THE WHOLE IDEA
FROM THE BEGINNING?
YEAH. WE'RE DEFINITELY SERIOUS
ABOUT BARBECUE.
SITTING ON THE PORCH?
SITTING ON THE PORCH.
SITTING ON A PORCH
HAVING THE SAME DREAM.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S GOOD STUFF.
NICE JOB, BROTHER.
THANKS.
EXCELLENT.
UP NEXT...
YOU'VE GOT
A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM --
ONE FROM NORCAL,
ONE FROM CHILE.
WE'RE HEADED
TO MANTEO, NORTH CAROLINA...
SHE MAKES IT HER WAY,
YOU MAKE IT YOUR WAY,
AND WHOEVER WINS
GETS PUT ON THE MENU?
YEP.
...FOR A GOOD, OLD-FASHIONED
TEX-MEX TAKEDOWN.
A GIRL FROM UKIAH
JUST SHOWING UP HER HUSBAND
SOMETHING FIERCE?
(Fieri) SO, I KNOW
YOU'RE SAYING TO YOURSELF,
"WHY IS GUY FIERI STANDING
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE ROAD
"IN DOWNTOWN MANTEO
ON ROANOKE ISLAND
JUST A FEW MILES AWAY
FROM NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA?"
WELL, IT'S TO CHECK OUT A JOINT
WHERE A DUDE FROM CHILE
MARRIES AND MEETS A GIRL
FROM MY NECK OF THE WOODS --
UKIAH --
AND THEY OPEN UP
EXACTLY WHAT YOU'D EXPECT
TO FIND
IN A SOUTHERN COASTAL TOWN...
(record scratches)
A SOUTHWESTERN GRILL
AND WINE BAR.
THIS IS ORTEGA'Z.
CHICKEN CHIMICHANGA.
IT'S SOMETHING
THAT YOU DON'T EXPECT.
WE COME HERE AT LEAST
FOUR OR FIVE TIMES A WEEK.
SOFT SHELLS
ARE GOING IN.
(woman) GREAT RESTAURANT,
GREAT ATMOSPHERE, GREAT
PEOPLE, GREAT FOOD.
PORK ENCHILADAS.
JUST LIKE MAMA COOKS.
REALLY?
YOUR MOM MADE MEXICAN FOOD?
NO.
MARCELO'S MOM.
THAT WOULD BE
CHILEAN-BORN MARCELO ORTEGA...
CHIMICHANGA WITH CHICKEN,
PLEASE.
GOT IT.
...WHO RUNS THE KITCHEN
WITH HIS WIFE, LISA.
FISH TACO UP.
WE LIKE
SOUTHWESTERN FOOD.
WE JUST WENT
WITH OUR NAME.
THAT'S WHY THEY OPENED
THIS PLACE IN 2007,
AND WHEN IT COMES
TO RUNNING THIS JOINT...
I GOT YOUR SOFT SHELLS.
...IT'S A TAG-TEAM EVENT.
(bell dings)
ONE PERSON'S
IN CHARGE OF THE KITCHEN.
ONE PERSON IS IN CHARGE
OF THE FRONT OF THE HOUSE
FOR SIX MONTHS.
SERIOUSLY?
SO, YOU RUN IT
FOR SIX MONTHS.
YEAH.
SHE COMES IN AND FIXES IT,
GIVES IT BACK TO YOU.
TOGETHER, THEY'RE COMBINING
SOUTH-OF-THE-BORDER CLASSICS
WITH OUTER BANKS FAVORITES.
ALL FRESH, LOCAL SEAFOOD.
(Lisa)
SOFT-SHELL QUESADILLA.
SOFT SHELLS ARE, LIKE,
VERY OUTER BANKS,
SO TO HAVE A QUESADILLA
THAT INCORPORATES SOFT SHELLS
IS PERFECT.
SOFT-SHELL CRAB
IS KIND OF LIKE THE STATE BIRD
AROUND HERE.
ABSOLUTELY.
AND THIS
IS GOING FOR WHAT DISH?
THE SOFT-SHELL CRAB
QUESADILLA.
OKAY.
YOU BRING THEM IN, CLEAN THEM.
TAKE THE MUSTARD
OUT OF THE SIDES.
TAKE THE GILLS OUT.
NOW WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
DREDGE THEM IN THE BUTTERMILK.
20, 25 MINUTES.
JUST ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF THAT ACID.
YEP.
NOW WE'RE GONNA MAKE
THE DREDGE.
A LITTLE PAPRIKA,
LITTLE WHITE PEPPER, GARLIC
SALT, A LITTLE CAYENNE PEPPER,
THYME, OREGANO,
AND LEMON PEPPER.
YOU FORGOT THIS.
A LITTLE KITCHEN SINK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN WE JUST MIX IT ALL UP.
SO, KIND OF A DRY RUB.
GONNA DREDGE THE...
THE SOFT SHELLS.
JUST GIVE THEM
A NICE, LITTLE BOUNCE AROUND.
THEY'RE
NOT SUPER HEAVY-COATED.
SHAKE IT OFF.
AND THEN JUST LAY THEM IN THERE.
350 IN THE FRYER?
YES.
NOW, WHILE THAT'S COOKING,
WHAT ARE WE INTO?
ONE 12-INCH TORTILLA.
LET IT GET HEATED UP THERE.
TAKE A LITTLE CHEESE.
NICE, EVEN COAT.
ALL RIGHT.
NEXT, OUR SAUTéED ANAHEIM
AND ONION.
ANAHEIM PEPPERS AND ONIONS
THAT HAVE BEEN SWEATED.
YEP.
TWO SOFT-SHELL CRAB
GO IN EACH ORDER.
YES.
HOLY MOLEY!
JUST LAY THAT GUY
RIGHT DOWN.
GET SOME CHEESE
GOING ON THE TOP.
AND THEN WHAT WE DO IS ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF LETTUCE TO IT.
LETTUCE IN A QUESADILLA?
YOU'RE GONNA GET ME RUN
OUT OF TOWN, MAN.
AND A LITTLE CILANTRO
JUST TO GIVE IT,
YOU KNOW,
A LITTLE MORE EARTHINESS.
THROW THAT THING UP NICE
LIKE THAT.
YOU'RE
AT THE GIANT TACO STAGE NOW.
QUESADILLA
LEFT THE BUILDING.
FLIP IT OVER AND GET
A NICE, LITTLE BROWN
ON THE OUTSIDE OF IT.
MARK IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
DIG IT.
THAT ISN'T A QUESADILLA.
THERE WE GO.
NOW, WHOSE RECIPE
IS THIS?
MINE, ALL THE WAY.
PUT A LITTLE GARNISH ON IT.
OKAY.
THERE YOU GO.
SOUR CREAM AND SALSA.
THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS LETTUCE
IN QUESADILLA, CHEF.
YOU'RE SCARING ME.
NICE, MAN.
I LIKE THE LETTUCE
AND THE VEGETABLE COMPONENT.
THE PEPPERS
ARE WHAT MAKE IT.
TWO SOFT-SHELL CRABS.
THIS IS WAY MORE
THAN A QUESADILLA.
IT'S A DELICIOUS DISH.
BUT THAT'S
FOUR GIGANTIC TACOS.
AND IN THE CHEESY
SOFT-SHELL-CRAB TACO MARKET,
THINK YOU KNOCKED IT OUT.
GREAT JOB.
THANKS.
SOFT-SHELL-CRAB QUESADILLA
FOR YOU.
(woman) IT'S DELICIOUS,
FIRST OF ALL. IT'S FRESH.
IT'S A GREAT SUMMER FOOD.
GOT A NICE PUNCH TO IT.
YOU KNOW, YOU WAIT
FOR SOFT-SHELLS EVERY YEAR,
AND THEN QUESADILLAS
ARE LIKE COMFORT FOOD.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
IT'S SO GOOD.
BAHA PORK ENCHILADA.
HOW DO YOU DESIGN
THE MENU HERE?
WE BOTH COME UP WITH IDEAS,
AND WE'RE SO COMPETITIVE
WITH WHAT WE DO,
WE NEVER REALLY COME
TO AN AGREEMENT.
SHE MAKES IT HER WAY,
YOU MAKE IT YOUR WAY,
AND THEN YOU GUYS HAVE
A TASTE-OFF,
YEAH.
AND WHOEVER WINS
GETS PUT ON THE MENU?
YEP.
I'VE GOT
A SEAFOOD PAELLA.
(Fieri)
WHO'S A BETTER COOK?
LISA.
(both laugh)
I SEE LOTS
OF FINGERS POINTING.
WELL, I GO MARCELO.
THEY'RE BOTH EQUALLY GOOD.
HONESTLY.
I'M NOT JUST SAYING THAT.
(smooching)
NO, I'M SERIOUS.
(laughing )
IT'S ALWAYS GOOD.
MARCELO, YOU GOT
THOSE FAJITAS WORKING?
(Marcelo)
IT'S COMING RIGHT UP.
I UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE'S A LITTLE COMPETITION
THAT GOES ON
BETWEEN THE TWO OF YOU.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
SO FAR, YOU'VE WON IN LOOKS,
LOCATION OF GROWING UP,
PERSONALITY --
OH, I'M SORRY.
(chuckles)
HE TOOK ME DOWN
TO THE LETTUCE QUESADILLA TEAM.
I WANT TO SEE
WHAT YOU'RE GONNA DO.
WE ARE GONNA DO
SOME BLACKFIN-TUNA TACOS.
LET'S SEE IT.
WE'RE GONNA START OUT
MAKING OUR TORTILLAS
WITH A LITTLE MASECA,
AND ADD A LITTLE BIT OF SALT
TO IT.
FRESH-GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
REALLY?
THAT'S A NEW ONE.
WATER.
ROOM TEMPERATURE.
I'LL SPOT YOU.
THANK YOU.
(Austrian accent)
YOU CAN DO IT, ROCKY.
YOU ONLY GOT
FOUR MORE ROUNDS TO GO.
I DON'T KNOW
WHY ARNOLD SCHWARZENEGGER
WAS JUST TELLING OFF ROCKY,
BUT...
JUST UP TILL IT'S TACKY.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE IT KIND
OF ABOUT THE SIZE OF
GOLF BALLS IN HERE.
WE GO DOWN.
AND THE KEY IS THE PLASTIC.
PEEL IT OFF.
ONTO THE FLAT TOP.
THROW IT ONTO THE FLAT TOP.
AND WE'RE GONNA DO THIS
WITH BLACKFIN TUNA?
BLACKFIN TUNA.
FRESH? LOCAL?
RIGHT OUT OF WANCHESE.
YOU'RE GONNA BUTCHER IT,
TOO?
WE ARE.
OH, THIS I GOT TO SEE.
YOU'RE SO FAR AHEAD
OF YOUR HUSBAND.
(chuckles)
SO, THEY COME IN CLEAN.
WE'RE GONNA START
AROUND THE BACK GILL.
CUT OFF THE HEAD.
THAT'S
A GOOD-LOOKING FISH.
GONNA GO ALONG
THE BLOODLINE RIGHT HERE.
OKAY.
YOU GET FOUR FILLETS
OUT OF THIS, PRETTY MUCH.
A GIRL FROM UKIAH
JUST SHOWING UP HER HUSBAND
SOMETHING FIERCE?
(laughs)
THIS IS WRONG.
NOW WE'RE GONNA BREAK IT UP.
SO, QUARTER-INCH PIECES.
SEASON IT UP
WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF OUR HOUSE
BLACKENING SEASONING.
MAKE SURE
YOU GET AN EVEN COATING.
I'M GONNA SAUTé THIS.
OKAY.
A LITTLE OIL.
ANY MEDIUM RARENESS
TO THIS,
OR ARE WE GOING
ALL THE WAY THROUGH?
WE ARE GONNA DO
MEDIUM RARE.
AS IT'S COOKING, WE'RE GONNA
ADD SOME FRESH-CRUSHED GARLIC.
OKAY.
SOME FRESH LIME.
FRESH LIME JUICE.
NICE.
AND FINALLY, CILANTRO.
I LIKE IT.
I'LL GET
OUR TORTILLAS READY.
(Fieri)
HAND-MADE TORTILLAS.
MEDIUM RARE.
I CANNOT BELIEVE
THE AMOUNT OF TUNA.
CILANTRO AND LIME SAUCE.
FINISH IT OFF
WITH SOME FRESH PICO DE GALLO.
PICO DE MíO?
TORTILLA ITSELF
IS SUPER SOFT AND SUPPLE.
MIGHT BE THE FIRST TIME
WE'VE EVER USED "SUPPLE."
THE FISH
IS INCREDIBLY FRESH.
YOU COULD'VE TAKEN THIS NAPKIN,
FOLDED IT,
AND PUT THAT FISH IN THERE,
AND IT WOULD'VE BEEN FANTASTIC.
THAT IS
A DYNAMITE FISH TACO.
THAT'S THE REAL DEAL.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
FISH TACOS.
(woman)
IT'S SPICY, BUT NOT TOO SPICY.
THE FLAVORS
JUST BLEND PERFECTLY.
I LOVE THE SOFT SHELL BECAUSE
IT REALLY COMPLEMENTS THE FISH.
THE SOUR CREAM
HAS A NICE LIME FLAVOR TO IT.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
YOU WANT THE SCORE
SO FAR?
ONE OUT OF FIVE,
YOUR HUSBAND.
HE GOT A THREE.
ONE OUT OF FIVE FOR YOU.
CINCO!
(laughs)
NICE JOB.
SO, WHEN WE COME BACK,
(bell dings)
YOUR HUSBAND STEPS
BACK INTO THE RING FOR ORTEGA'Z.
WHAT'S HE GONNA MAKE?
HE'S GONNA MAKE A SHRIMP
AND CHORIZO ALFREDO.
SHRIMP AND CHORIZO ALFREDO
IN A MEXICAN RESTAURANT?
THIS SHOULD BE GOOD.
SEE YOU IN A BIT.
(Fieri)
YOU FEEL GOOD NOW.
YEAH. SHRIMP.
OKAY.
PRESSURE'S ON.
LET HER ROLL.
CHEF ORTEGA
GOING HEAD-TO-HEAD
AGAINST HIS WIFE
IN A BATTLE ROYAL.
NO, THIS IS NOT "IRON CHEF."
THIS IS TRIPLE D.
WE'RE HANGING OUT IN MANTEO,
RIGHT OUTSIDE
OF NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA.
I'M READY.
WHAT ARE WE MAKING?
SHRIMP AND CHORIZO PASTA.
OKAY.
FIRST UP, POBLANOS.
YEAH.
WE'RE TAKING THE POBLANOS,
AND WE'RE JUST LAYING THEM
RIGHT ON THE CHARBROILER
AND START ROASTING.
WE'RE GONNA ROAST THEM,
SWEAT THEM.
PEEL THE ROASTED POBLANOS,
DE-SEED THEM,
AND GIVE THEM A ROUGH CHOP.
AND THEN THEY'RE GONNA GO
INTO THE...
PESTO.
THIS IS A POBLANO PESTO?
YEP. ROASTED POBLANO
AND SUN-DRIED TOMATO PESTO.
RE-HYDRATED
SUN-DRIED TOMATO.
CILANTRO.
PINE NUTS.
MANCHEGO.
YOU GET THAT OUT HERE?
YEAH.
AND THE WORCESTERSHIRE.
ANY OIL GOING IN THERE?
YEAH.
WE'LL KIND OF PUT THE OIL
IN THERE AS WE'RE MIXING IT.
YOUR RECIPE AGAIN?
ABSOLUTELY.
GET A LITTLE TASTE.
AND THAT'S GONNA GO IN...
THAT'S GONNA GO
IN THE PASTA.
NICE BEGINNING.
HAVE YOUR GAME ON.
SEE YOUR WIFE STARING YOU DOWN
RIGHT NOW.
(whistling)
MY POINTS ARE COMING UP.
NEXT UP, WE START BUILDING
THE DISH?
YEP.
LET'S SEE YOU, BUDDY.
OIL IN THE PAN.
CHORIZO.
YES.
IS THIS HOW YOU GET
YOUR SHRIMP HERE?
WE CAN EITHER GET THEM
HEADS ON OR HEADS OFF.
LOCAL, FRESH?
YEAH. LOCAL, FRESH.
RIGHT OUT OF THE SOUND.
SERIOUSLY?
YOU GUYS ARE SPOILED.
NOW I'M GONNA GO TO THE --
MUSHROOMS AND TOMATOES.
YEP.
OKAY. LITTLE CREMINI.
GRAPE TOMATOES.
I LIKE
THE WAY THIS IS GOING.
TOSS THE PASTA IN THERE.
ROASTED POBLANO PESTO
WITH THE SUN-DRIED TOMATOES.
DOING GOOD. COME ON, MAN!
YOU CAN DO IT!
LET'S HEAR IT FOR HIM,
EVERYBODY.
(cheers and applause)
LITTLE CHICKEN STOCK.
CHICKEN STOCK.
LITTLE DEGLAZE THERE.
IN-HOUSE
BLACKENING SPICE AGAIN.
YEP.
DROP THOSE SHRIMP DOWN.
LET THEM BUILD
A LITTLE CRUST.
LITTLE CREAM.
COOKING IT DOWN.
MANCHEGO.
YEP.
OH. YAHTZEE.
SOMEBODY WINS.
EVERYBODY WINS.
LOOK AT THOSE PAN SKILLS
ON THAT CAT.
LAST BUT NOT LEAST...
SPINACH.
WILT A LITTLE SPINACH.
HOLY MOLEY, SPINACH CAPTAIN.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
TOMATOES, MUSHROOMS,
THE SAUSAGE,
THE LOCAL SHRIMP.
OKAY. IT'S READY.
VERY NICE.
MMM.
GREAT SAUSAGE.
WITH THAT PESTO IN THERE,
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
YOU DON'T GET A PASTA DISH
IN A MEXICAN RESTAURANT.
I THINK THAT'S REALLY NICE.
AND THE SPINACH, TO ME,
IS REALLY THE KICKER.
ADDS SOME GREAT COLOR.
GOOD BALANCE.
WAY TO DO IT.
THE QUESTION IS,
DID YOU WIN?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOUR WIFE
BUTCHERED THE FISH,
AND THAT'S
THE WINNING POINT.
YOU'RE GONNA BE WASHING
A LOT OF DISHES, MY FRIEND.
GREAT PASTA.
ALL RIGHT.         THANK YOU.
THANKS A LOT.
SHRIMP AND CHORIZO ALFREDO.
THE CHORIZO TASTES WONDERFUL,
AND THE CREAM SAUCE HAS
A REALLY PEPPERY FLAVOR TO IT.
KIND OF BITES, AND IT'S AMAZING.
I TREAT MYSELF TO THIS
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
I LOVE IT.
TEQUILA LIME CHICKEN.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THIS IS THE KIND OF FOOD
THAT GETS ALONG.
I MEAN, EVERYBODY DIGS THIS.
IT'S A HEART-AND-SOUL PLACE
FOR ME.
YOU'VE GOT
A HUSBAND-AND-WIFE TEAM --
ONE FROM NORCAL,
ONE FROM CHILE,
THREE KIDS,
SOUTHWESTERN FOOD
IN A COASTAL SOUTHERN TOWN
IN NORTH CAROLINA.
I MEAN, THAT IS
A MADE-FOR-TV MOVIE.
GOOD JOB ON THAT FISH,
BY THE WAY.
THANK YOU.
OKAY. CHAMPION.
MAKE SURE
HE WASHES THE DISHES.
SO, THAT'S IT
FOR THIS FLAVORTOWN ROAD TRIP,
BUT DON'T YOU WORRY.
THERE'S PLENTY MORE JOINTS
ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING FOR YOU
NEXT TIME
ON "DINERS, DRIVE-INS,
AND DIVES."
(Austrian accent)
GOOD JOB, CHAMPION.
YES, YOU DID GREAT.
IT'S WHEN YOU DID THE FINAL BIT
WITH THE FISH,
AND YOU DIDN'T OVERCOOK IT --
THAT IS WHY YOU PREVAIL
OVER YOUR HUSBAND.
(laughter)