HEY THERE, I'M GUY FIERI
AND WE'RE ROLLIN' OUT,
LOOKIN' FOR AMERICA'S GREATEST
DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES.
(Guy) THIS TRIP...
OHH!
WE'RE TACKING ON
ONE MORE "D"...
I DON'T WANT TO USE
THE WORD "DELECTABLE."
NOPE, "DEDICATION."
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
WELL, NOW I DO.
IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK...
THIS IS BALLER.
"BALLER'S" MY WORD.
THE DOWNTOWN PASTA BAR...
I CAN'T COME BACK
AND HANG OUT WITH YOU ANYMORE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
COMMITTED TO SUPER SAUCES...
YOU NEED, LIKE,
A SPECIAL LICENSE TO SERVE THAT.
STANDOUT PIES...
PROBABLY ONE OF THE BEST
DUCK DISHES I'VE EVER HAD.
AND EVEN A REGIONAL ROCK STAR.
WICKY-WICKY.
DID YOU JUST THROW
A WICKY-WICKY?
AND IN
NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA,
THE PIER-SIDE JOINTS...
THIS IS WHERE
IT GETS A LITTLE MESSY.
LOCKING IN
SOUTHERN TRADITIONS...
FRIED PICKLES.
AND THE BOUNTY OF THE COUNTY.
THERE'S JUST NO WAY
TO IMPROVE ON THAT.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT HERE,
RIGHT NOW, ON TRIPLE "D."
♪♪
I'M HERE IN ARMORY SQUARE
IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK.
YOU SEE THAT JOINT RIGHT THERE?
SHOT TRIPLE "D" THERE.
IT'S CALLED KITTY HOYNES.
IT'S, LIKE,
THE REAL-DEAL IRISH PUB.
AND NOW I'M DIRECTLY
ACROSS THE STREET.
I MEAN, THIS IS KIND OF LIKE,
UH, LIKE A TRIPLE "D"
DOUBLE DIP.
THIS PLACE HERE, I HEAR
THEY MAKE THEIR OWN SAUCE,
THEY MAKE THEIR OWN BREAD,
AND THEY MAKE THEIR OWN PASTA.
I MEAN, THE "PASTABILITIES"
ARE ENDLESS.
THE PASTA IS HOMEMADE.
YOU CAN JUST TASTE
THAT FRESH DIFFERENCE.
THEY HAVE RECIPES THAT
YOU CAN'T GET ANYWHERE ELSE...
THANKS TO OWNER
KARYN KORTELING...
FLATBREAD UP.
WHO'S BEEN PERFECTING THE MENU
SINCE '82.
WHEN WE STARTED,
WE HAD $15,000 ABOUT.
YOU STARTED YOUR FIRST JOINT
WITH 15 GRAND?
WELL, IT WAS SELF-SERVICE
CAFETERIA-STYLE.
OKAY, IT STARTED, IT MORPHED, IT
CHANGED, AND THEN YOU EXPLODED.
YEP.
YOU CAN ASK ALMOST
ANYBODY IN THIS TOWN
HAVE THEY BEEN TO PASTABILITIES,
AND THEIR RESPONSE WOULD BE...
"I LOVE THAT PLACE."
THIS IS HOME.
I MEAN, THIS JOINT'S
SO POPULAR,
LOCALS JUST CALL IT
BY ITS FIRST NAME.
YOU CALL IT "PASTA'S"?
OH, ALL THE LOCALS DO,
MM-HMM.
WHEN YOU KNOW IT THAT WELL,
YOU JUST GO,
"OH, I'M GOING
TO PASTA'S."
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
WELL, NOW I DO.
HERE'S ANOTHER INSIDER TIP--
NEVER, AND I MEAN NEVER PASS
ON KARYN'S FAMOUS APPETIZER.
THE HOT TOMATO OIL--
IT'S A WAY OF LIFE HERE.
ALL RIGHT, SO THE FIRST THING
WE'RE GONNA START OFF WITH?
SPICY HOT TOMATO OIL.
LET'S FIRE IT UP.
PURE OLIVE OIL...
OKAY.
SLICED GARLIC.
CARAMELIZE IT
FOR ABOUT 15 MINUTES.
SO JUST GO
LOW AND SLOW.
SO THE OIL HAS BEEN PERFUMED NOW
WITH THE DELICIOUS GARLIC.
THAT'S RIGHT.
OKAY, NEXT UP?
ADD OUR TOMATO PURéE.
JUST REGULAR OLD
TOMATOES?
THEY'RE
CALIFORNIA TOMATOES.
AS THEY SHOULD BE.
SALT, A LITTLE BIT
OF HONEY.
GOT IT.
CHILI MIXTURE.
NEXT, THE RESERVED OIL.
THE OIL THAT HAD
THE GARLIC FLAVOR.
YEP.
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUT
THE BIG GUNS.
WHOA. WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
GOING IN.
THAT'S IT.
(laughing) THAT'S IT.
WE GET TO STIR
OUR GARLIC BACK IN.
'CAUSE YOU WANT
TO SEE THE CHUNKS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AND NOW WE'RE READY
TO TASTE IT?
NOW WE'RE READY
TO TASTE IT.
SO WHEN SOMEONE
COMES IN HERE,
THIS IS WHAT THEY GET
TO KICK OFF THEIR MEAL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE FAMOUS FOR.
AND THIS IS SOME
OF YOUR BREAD.
THAT'S OUR STRETCH BREAD.
THAT'S CRAZY.
OHH!
I CAN'T COME BACK
AND HANG OUT WITH YOU ANYMORE.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
IT JUST 100% REMINDS ME
OF DAY-OLD SPAGHETTI,
WHICH IN MY WORLD,
IS A VERY IMPORTANT THING.
THIS HAS THAT SAME FLAVOR
AND A LITTLE BIT OF THE OIL.
IT'S VERY SMOOTH.
THE INTENSITY OF THE FLAVOR
OF GARLIC IS, OF COURSE, THERE.
IT'S NOT OVERLY SPICY
BY ANY MEANS.
OHH, YOU NEED, LIKE,
A SPECIAL LICENSE TO SERVE THAT.
HOT OIL UP.
IT'S LIKE NOTHING ELSE.
(man) IT'S ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
THE FIRST TIME I HAD IT
YEARS AGO I WAS ADDICTED.
JUST, LIKE, BEGGING THE WAITRESS
TO GIVE THAT TO YOU.
AND KARYN'S ABILITY
TO ATTRACT A CROWD
ISN'T JUST LIMITED TO FOOD.
THE RESTAURANT WAS
PRETTY MUCH THE GENESIS
OF DOWNTOWN SYRACUSE.
HER LATEST CREATION--
A FULL-SERVICE BAKERY
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET,
WHERE SHE'S CRANKING OUT
KILLER FRENCH BREAD
FOR THE TOMATO OIL
AND ROLLIN' OUT DOUGH
FOR A FLATBREAD PIZZA
TOPPED WITH--
GET THIS--DUCK BACON.
IT'S REALLY UNIQUE.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT.
FULL OF FLAVOR. IT'S PHENOMENAL.
ALL RIGHT,
SO GIVE ME THE RUNDOWN--
HOW ARE WE DOING THIS?
WE'RE GONNA DO
A RUB FIRST.
WE START WITH MINCED GARLIC,
CRACKED PEPPER,
SUGAR, FRESH ROSEMARY,
FRESH SAGE...
A BUNCH OF SALT.
AND...
A LITTLE PINK
HAIR DYE.
PINK SALT,
AND I BLEND IT ALL UP.
MMM!
NOW WE'RE GONNA
PUT THE RUB ON THE DUCK.
HOW LONG ARE YOU
GONNA LET THIS GO?
SEVEN DAYS.
ALL RIGHT, SO WE'RE CURING
THIS DUCK IS WHAT WE'RE DOING.
BUT WE'RE REALLY GONNA BE
PULLING THE MOISTURE OUT,
WHICH IS GONNA BE GREAT,
BECAUSE THAT LENDS ITSELF
TO WHEN YOU SMOKE IT THAT
IT'S GONNA GIVE IT A CHANCE
TO REALLY TIGHTEN UP AND BE NICE
AND FIRM TO MAKE BACON, CORRECT?
THAT'S CORRECT.
OKAY, DUCK'S SET TO GO.
SMOKER'S READY?
SMOKER'S READY.
SKIN SIDE UP?
YEP.
SO THAT'S GONNA GO
AN HOUR AND A HALF...
HOUR AND A HALF.
LUMP CHARCOAL AND A LITTLE BIT
OF APPLEWOOD.
YEP.
NOW THAT
THE DUCK BREAST IS OFF,
WE MAKE A LITTLE
POMEGRANATE SYRUP
JUST TO ADD
A LITTLE MORE FLAVOR.
OKAY.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
SLICE THIS BACON.
VERY THIN.
NICE AND THIN SO IT WILL
CRISP UP A LITTLE BIT.
♪♪
THAT MIGHT ACTUALLY BE
SACRILEGIOUS
TO EVEN PUT THAT
ON ANYTHING ELSE.
WELL, LET'S SEE IT.
FLATBREAD,
PUT A LITTLE GARLIC OIL,
FRESH MOZZARELLA. SO WE LIKE
A LOT OF MOZZ ON HERE.
DRIED CHERRIES--YOU KNOW,
WE LIKE THE SWEET AND SAVORY,
CARAMELIZED ONIONS,
OUR HUMBOLT FOG GOAT CHEESE.
A LITTLE BIT--
YOU KNOW WHY THEY CALL IT
HUMBOLT FOG?
UM, NO, I DON'T.
I KNOW IT'S FOGGY.
DO YOU SEE HOW--DO YOU SEE
HOW I JUST DISTRACTED YOU
WHILE I ATE THAT OTHER PIECE
OF THAT DUCK
ASKING YOU RANDOM QUESTIONS?
SO SLY.
WHY DO THEY CALL IT
HUMBOLT FOG?
HUMBOLT IS ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL PLACES IN THE WORLD,
BUT THE CRAZY THING IS
IS WE DO GET, LIKE,
THIS ABUNDANCE--
ABOUT AS MUCH FOG
AS YOU JUST PUT ON THAT PIZZA
IS THE KIND OF FOG WE GET.
NOW OUR SMOKED
DUCK BACON.
IN THE OVEN
FOR HOW LONG?
12 MINUTES.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA
FINISH IT IN THE SALAMANDER...
IN THE SALAMANDER.
JUST TO PUT A NICE LITTLE CRISP
ON THAT--ON THAT BACON ON TOP.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHOO! GOT IT?
YEAH, I GOT IT.
THAT'S THE FINAL
LITTLE CRISP ON THAT.
NOW WE PUT A LITTLE MORE
POMEGRANATE SYRUP ON IT.
OF COURSE WE DO.
A LITTLE CRACKED PEPPER.
BASIL, PARSLEY.
THE CRUST ON THIS FLATBREAD
IS RIGHTEOUS.
SO THE BREAD HAS
SUCH GREAT CHEW.
THE FRESH MOZZ,
TARTNESS OF THAT CHERRY,
A LITTLE BIT OF
"FUNKALICIOUSNESS"
COMING FROM THAT
HUMBOLT FOG.
NOBODY TAKES THE LEAD ROLE
EXCEPT THE DUCK BACON.
IT'S PROBABLY ONE OF THE BEST
DUCK DISHES I'VE EVER HAD.
YEAH, YOU--YOU JACKPOTTED
ON THAT ONE, GIRL. WOW!
EXCELLENT.
MMM.
FLATBREAD PIZZA'S UP.
IT'S PROBABLY ONE OF
THE BEST PIZZAS I'VE EVER HAD.
THIS IS BALLER.
IT'S AWESOME.
"BALLER'S" MY WORD.
(laughing)
AND WE'RE NOT DONE YET...
WHOA. WHOA!
'CAUSE WHEN WE COME BACK...
HOW HOT IS THAT?
THAT'S THE WICKED.
WE'RE SHARING ONE OF
SYRACUSE'S BEST-KEPT SECRETS.
WICKY-WICKY.
DID YOU JUST THROW
A WICKY-WICKY?
(turntable scratches)
WICKY-WICKY.
AT PASTABILITIES
IN SYRACUSE, NEW YORK,
OWNER KARYN KORTELING'S BEEN
CRANKING OUT SCRATCH-MADE PASTA
AND PIES
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
JUST A GREAT PLACE
TO COME AND HANG OUT.
AND SHE'S TURNING UP THE HEAT
ON A REGIONAL DISH
THAT DRIVES LOCALS CRAZY.
I'VE GOT THE WICKED CHICKEN
RIGGIES RIGHT HERE.
IT'S SPICY
BUT WITH A GREAT FLAVOR.
IT CAN'T BE REPLICATED.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S A CENTRAL NEW YORK DISH--
OUR WICKED CHICKEN RIGGIES.
(laughs) TIME OUT.
IT'S CALLED RIGGIES?
RIGGIES ARE RIGATONI.
THESE PARTS,
CHICKEN RIGGIES RULE.
OKAY, LET'S START
THE RIGGIES.
FIRST, WE'RE GONNA
START WITH OLIVE OIL,
GARLIC, SWEET ONION,
AND WE'LL JUST LET THAT
SIMMER FOR A MOMENT.
THEN WE GO TO OUR PEPPERS--
YELLOW PEPPERS, SWEET RED,
GREEN, A LITTLE JALAPEÑO.
SO THIS HAS GOT
SOME SPICE TO IT?
WELL, WE CALL IT "WICKED"
FOR A REASON, YOU KNOW?
OREGANO.
RED CHILI FLAKE.
CAYENNE.
THE PEPPER-TO-EVERYTHING-ELSE
RATIO IS STARTING TO GO UP.
SALT, DRIED BASIL,
AND BLACK PEPPER.
AND NEXT UP, THIS
BEAUTIFUL TOMATO SAUCE.
YEP, THIS IS OUR
HOUSE TOMATO SAUCE.
WHAT'S THIS LITTLE--
OH, THAT'S THE WICKED.
THIS IS THE WICKED?
THAT'S THE WICKED.
HOW HOT IS THAT?
I'D SAY IT'S HOT.
IT'S, UH, CHIPOTLE PEPPERS,
CHILI PEPPERS, CHILI-SPICED OIL.
YOU'RE NOT JOKING
WHEN YOU CALL IT WICKED.
MNH-MNH.
ALL RIGHT, CREAM.
LET IT SIMMER
FOR 45 MINUTES
JUST TO GET ALL THE PEPPER
GOODNESS IN THERE.
ADD THE SUGAR,
ROMANO CHEESE.
WHOA. WHOA!
WHOA! WE JUST WENT
TO, UH, SPICY TOMATO ALFREDO.
HUH, GOOD WAY
TO EXPLAIN IT?
THAT WOULD BE
A GOOD WAY TO EXPLAIN IT.
SO WE LET IT
SIMMER DOWN...
YEP.
AND NEXT, WE'LL
WORK ON WHAT?
THEN WE GOT
TO CHICKEN IT.
WE'RE GONNA CHICKEN IT?
WE'RE GONNA CHICKEN IT.
SLICED CHICKEN BREAST,
A LITTLE SALT AND PEPPER.
SO THE CHICKEN'S,
UH, BROWNED UP NICELY.
YEP.
A FEW LADLES OF
CREAM CHICKY RIGGY SAUCE,
AND I POUR
MY RIGGIES IN.
COAT IT ALL.
THERE YOU GO.
NICE, AND SHE'S DONE.
THERE WE GO.
GARNISH WITH
LOCATELLI CHEESE
AND GREEN ONION.
AND THAT'S RIGGIES.
CHICKEN RIGGIES--
WICKED.
WICKED CHICKEN RIGGIES.
MMM.
MMM!
WINNER, WINNER,
WICKED CHICKEN DINNER.
YOU KNOW, NOT ONLY HAVE YOU BEAT
ME IN THE BLOND DEPARTMENT...
AW.
THE HEIGHT DEPARTMENT,
BUT NOW YOU JUST ROLLED OUT
"WINNER, WINNER,
WICKED CHICKEN DINNER."
(laughs)
IT'S AN AWESOME DISH.
I'M SO GLAD.
PASTA'S NICE,
NOT TOO MUCH SAUCE,
NOT OVERLY SPICY.
A REAL SIMPLE DISH, BUT QUALITY
INGREDIENTS MADE THE RIGHT WAY,
AND IT'S A STAPLE HERE
AT PASTABILITIES.
THAT'S RIGHT.
LOVE IT.
RIGGIES UP.
(man) A LOT OF RESTAURANTS TRY
AND HAVE THE CHICKEN RIGGIES,
BUT ONLY A COUPLE OF 'EM
ACTUALLY DO IT RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S OUR FAVORITE
RESTAURANT TO GO TO,
WHETHER IT'S LUNCH, DINNER,
REALLY ANYTHING.
UH, THE FOOD'S ALWAYS GOOD,
SO WE KEEP COMING BACK.
(Guy) DO YOU THINK THIS WOULD BE
WHAT IT CALL CAME TO?
I DIDN'T KNOW WHERE
I WAS GOING WITH THIS.
I JUST LOVE FOOD,
YOU KNOW?
WELL, IT COMES TO YOU
REALLY WELL.
THANKS.
'CAUSE I DO TRIPLE "D," THIS
IS WHAT I'M TRYING TO FIND--
EVERYDAY PEOPLE
MAKING REAL HANDMADE FOOD
WORKING WITH THEIR FAMILY,
WORKING WITH THEIR FRIENDS,
WORKING WITH THEIR COMMUNITY,
AND DOING WHAT'S RIGHT.
VERY PROUD OF YOU.
THANKS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADED
TO NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA...
THESE ARE MY KIND
OF PICKLES. OHH!
FOR A THROWBACK
SOUTHERN SPOT...
THIS MIGHT BE THE BEST
PICKLE CHIP I'VE EVER HAD.
THAT'S AS FRESH AS IT GETS.
FROM ALIVE TO YOUR PLATE
IN ABOUT EIGHT MINUTES.
♪♪
I'M HERE
IN NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA,
ON THE CAUSEWAY BETWEEN
THE BARRIER ISLANDS
AND ROANOKE ISLAND.
NOW THEY SAY THE WEATHER--
OH, DON'T WORRY ABOUT THIS.
IT'LL BLOW THROUGH. NOT THE DAY
TO DRIVE A CONVERTIBLE.
I'M HERE TO CHECK OUT
A FUNKY LITTLE JOINT.
THEIR MOTTO IS "GET PICKLED."
THIS IS THE BRINE AND BOTTLE.
(man) SHRIMP & GRITS.
ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
EVERYTHING'S DELICIOUS.
(man) IT'S GREAT TO GET THE
LOCAL OUTER BANKS SEAFOOD HERE,
UH, FRESH EVERY DAY.
I GOT A SOFT-SHELL
READY TO GO.
YOU WON'T FIND ANYTHING LIKE IT.
YOU'LL HAVE FABULOUS FOOD,
AND THE WINE PAIRINGS
TO GO WITH THE FOOD
PERFECTLY MATCHED.
MAKES SINCE,
SINCE CHEF ANDREW DONOVAN
TEAMED UP WITH
SOMMELIER ASHLEY WHITFIELD
TO OPEN THIS JOINT IN 2010,
GETTING ENGAGED IN THE PROCESS.
WE MADE IT THROUGH
THE FIRST WINTER
AND WE STILL LIKED EACH OTHER,
SO WE FIGURED--YEAH.
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
CONTINUE OUT THIS.
SO EXPLAIN
THE JOINT TO ME.
COASTAL SOUTHERN,
WITH A HEAVY INFLUENCE
ON PICKLING, PRESERVING,
CHUTNEYS--EVERYTHING A SOUTHERN
KITCHEN SHOULD HAVE...
TOTALLY AGREE, ESPECIALLY
WHEN THAT KITCHEN'S COMBINING
PICKLING AND FRYING
FOR THIS SOUTHERN CLASSIC.
(Andrew) AND HERE ARE
THE HOUSE FRIED PICKLES.
THE BRINY TASTE OF THE PICKLE
WITH THE BUTTERMILK CHIVE DIP--
JUST DELICIOUS.
YOU CAN'T STOP EATING THEM.
WHAT ARE WE
GONNA MAKE?
FRIED PICKLES.
LET'S DO IT.
WHERE ARE THE PICKLES FROM?
RALEIGH STATE
FARMERS MARKET.
SOME PEOPLE PLAY THE VIOLIN.
YOU PLAY THE MANDOLINE.
YOU KNOW,
JUST RUN IT FAST.
OKAY.
THAT THIN--WE'RE GONNA
FRY 'EM THAT THIN.
OH, YEAH.
I LIKE THIS.
OKAY, NEXT STEP?
CANNING
AND PICKLING SALT.
I'M JUST GONNA
MIX THAT UP.
YOU LEARN IT FROM ANYBODY?
YOUR MOM USED TO MAKE PICKLES?
MY GRANDMOTHER WAS A BIG
CANNING/PRESERVING PERSON.
SALT'S DOWN. NEXT?
IT'S GONNA SIT
FOR FOUR HOURS.
GREAT. PULL OUT
THE MOISTURE?
AND WE JUST SET IT ASIDE.
OKAY, FOUR HOURS GONE BY.
NEXT UP?
WE'RE GONNA HIT IT
WITH OUR SPICES--
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF WHOLE YELLOW MUSTARD SEED,
CRUSHED RED PEPPER,
AND JUST TOSS THAT AROUND
A LITTLE BIT.
MAKE THE BRINE.
YEAH--CIDER VINEGAR,
WATER.
WE'RE GONNA GO AHEAD AND GET
ALL THE--THE SUGAR IN THERE.
OKAY.
A LITTLE BUT
OF TURMERIC.
IT'S GOT TURMERIC.
JUST NEEDS TO BOIL ONCE
TO DISSOLVE THE SUGAR
AND THAT'S IT.
YOU WANT TO POUR IT BOILING
RIGHT OVER THE VEGETABLES.
THEN IT'LL GO INTO
REFRIGERATION FOR THREE WEEKS.
NEXT UP?
MAKE SOME SAUCE
FOR THE PICKLES.
SOUR CREAM,
A LITTLE BUTTERMILK.
SO WE'RE MAKING A LITTLE RANCH?
WHAT ARE WE MAKING HERE?
BASICALLY.
A LITTLE CIDER VINEGAR.
A.C.V.
JUST GONNA WHISK THAT
ALL TOGETHER.
OKAY.
FRESH CRACKED
BLACK PEPPER.
GOT IT.
A LITTLE KOSHER SALT...
OKAY.
AND A LITTLE
GRANULATED SUGAR.
FRESH CHIVES,
AND THE DILL.
LOVE FRESH DILL.
AND THAT'S ALL SHE WROTE.
THAT'S IT.
(whistles sharply)
OH, THAT'S GOT CRUNCH.
MMM.
LET'S TAKE A LITTLE
HANDFUL HERE.
OKAY.
THE BRINE IS WHAT
HOLDS IT TO THE FLOUR.
GET ALL THIS FLOUR
SIFTED OFF OF HERE.
STICK 'EM RIGHT
IN THE FRYER.
THESE ARE MY KIND OF PICKLES.
OHH!
SEASON WITH
A LITTLE SALT.
DON'T THROW 'EM
EVERYWHERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT
BUTTERMILK CHIVE WE MADE.
BIG PILES OF 'EM
ONTO THE PLATE. THAT'S IT.
YEAH, THIS MIGHT BE THE BEST
PICKLE CHIP I'VE EVER HAD.
THIN CHIP,
NICE AND CRISPY.
THAT IS THE PERFECT AMOUNT
OF BRINE, VINEGAR,
SWEET, SALT,
CRUNCH, TENDERNESS.
OH!
THE DILL COMPLEMENTS
THAT PICKLE BRINE--PHENOMENAL.
IF YOU LOOK IN THE DICTIONARY
AND YOU WANT A PICKLE CHIP,
THAT'S A PICKLE CHIP.
WELL DONE.
THANK YOU.
(Andrew)
FRIED HOUSE PICKLES ARE UP.
IT'S DIFFERENT THAN ANYTHING
ELSE WE HAVE HERE ON THE BEACH.
WE ENJOY THAT SO MUCH.
THESE GUYS ARE ALL ABOUT
GETTING BACK TO THEIR ROOTS.
(Andrew) WE PICKLE/PRESERVE
ALL THESE CHUTNEYS AND THINGS,
'CAUSE IT WAS A WAY OF LIFE
FOR SOUTHERNERS.
AND YOU HAVE THE BOUNTY OF
THE COUNTY IN THE RIGHT SEASON.
AND WHAT AIN'T
PICKLED OR PRESERVED
IS RIDICULOUSLY FRESH.
(man) SOFT-SHELL SANDWICH
FOR YOU.
(woman) WITH SOFT-SHELL CRAB,
YOU KNOW,
YOU EAT THE WHOLE CRAB.
IT'S FRIED PERFECTLY.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA MAKE?
SOFT-SHELL CRAB SANDWICH.
WE GET 'EM WHILE
THEY'RE IN THEIR PRIME.
YEAH, WELL, WE GOT
TO CLEAN 'EM UP FIRST
SO THAT WE CAN COOK 'EM.
YOU'RE TALKING FRESH.
THAT'S IT.
WE'RE GONNA SEASON
WITH A LITTLE SALT...
OKAY.
THEN UNSEASONED FLOUR. I ONLY
DREDGE THE TOP PART THERE.
YOU JUST GET A NICE
LITTLE COATING ON THE--
JUST SOME CRUNCH.
ON THAT SHELL.
NICE HOT PAN. JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF CANOLA OIL.
SO YOU'RE--YOU'RE GOING
FROM LIVE, CLEANED, AND COOKED
WITHIN...
ABOUT EIGHT MINUTES
FROM ALIVE
TO YOUR PLATE.
THAT IS AMAZING.
KEEP THAT GUY
IN THE OVEN.
LET IT FINISH OFF
YEAH, TWO MINUTES OR SO.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF WHOLE BUTTER.
A LITTLE BIT, HUH?
AND BASTE HIM UP
A LITTLE BIT.
CRAB'S RESTING.
NEXT UP?
GOT A TOASTED BUN HERE--
JUST A POTATO ROLL.
JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF PICKLED RAMP TARTAR.
OKAY.
SLICE OF TOMATO,
SOFT-SHELL CRAB.
JUST A COUPLE LITTLE
TOP HATS FOR THE GUY.
AND THAT'S IT.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S WHOLESOME GOODNESS.
MMM.
YOU CAN TASTE
THE SOFT-SHELL CRAB SO MUCH.
I THINK FIRST BECAUSE
IT'S FRESH, JUST PROCESSED,
A LITTLE BIT OF FLOUR,
SIMPLY SEASONED,
BASTED WITH A LITTLE BIT
OF WHOLE BUTTER.
THE RAMP TARTAR SAUCE
JUST COMPLEMENTING.
I MEAN, THERE'S JUST
NO WAY TO IMPROVE ON THAT.
THAT'S THAT GOOD. NICE JOB,
CHEF. REALLY, REALLY NICE JOB.
SURE, THANKS.
MMM. AND WHEN WE
COME BACK, CHEF ANDREW,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA
UNLEASH ON US?
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A LITTLE
FOIE GRAS TORCHON--
SOME PEACH MARMALADE, A LITTLE
BRIOCHE FROM A LOCAL BAKERY,
AND SOME SEA SALT.
AND WE'RE AT THE BEACH.
SEE YOU IN A LITTLE BIT.
♪♪
WELCOME BACK
TO NAGS HEAD, NORTH CAROLINA.
HANGING OUT WITH CHEF ANDREW
AT BRINE AND BOTTLE.
WE HAVE HAD
KILLER FRIED PICKLES,
INCREDIBLE
SOFT-SHELL CRAB,
AND NOW FOIE GRAS.
YOU GOT TO LOVE
A LITTLE GOOSE LIVER.
WHOO, LOOK AT THAT LOBE.
THAT'S A MONSTER.
YEAH, BIG GUY.
AND HOW ARE WE DOING THIS?
KIND OF BREAK
THESE GUYS APART.
PUT IT INTO A BOWL
WITH SALT,
CRACKED BLACK PEPPER,
JUST A TOUCH
OF GRANULATED SUGAR,
A LITTLE HONEY LIQUEUR.
REALLY?
YEAH, THE SWEET'S
GONNA HELP CUT THE FAT.
DOCTOR.
UH-OH.
THEN WE'RE JUST GONNA
EVENLY COAT IT.
WE'RE GONNA GO RIGHT INTO
ROLLING IT IN THE CHEESECLOTH.
IN THE CHEESECLOTH,
GOT IT.
FRONT OF THE CHEESECLOTH
THERE.
OKAY.
THIS IS WHERE
IT GETS A LITTLE MESSY.
TIGHTEN IT UP,
STARTING TO PRESS IT OUT.
IF YOU WANT TO TIE THAT OFF,
I'D GREATLY APPRECIATE IT.
WE'LL POACH IT.
IT'S JUST WATER,
SALT, GRANULATED SUGAR.
PINK PEPPERCORN.
A COUPLE OF BAY LEAVES.
OKAY, SO WE'RE SIMMERING.
NOW WE DROP.
YEAH, AND WE'LL POACH IT
FOR--FOR 90 SECONDS.
THEN WE'LL--
THAT'S IT--90 SECONDS?
THAT'S IT.
JUST ENOUGH
TO HEAT UP ALL THE FAT
SO IT'LL CONGEAL
BACK TOGETHER TIGHT...
CORRECT.
ONCE YOU DROP IT INTO THE WATER.
OKAY, SO 90 SECONDS OUT,
AND...
SHOCK IT IN AN ICE BATH.
LET THIS SIT 10, 15 MINUTES,
TILL IT REALLY CONGEALS.
YEP.
THEN WE'LL TAKE IT,
REWRAP IT?
REWRAP IT.
NOT NEARLY AS MESSY
THIS GO-ROUND.
MAKE SURE
WE'RE GOOD AND TIGHT.
AND THAT'S
ALL SHE WROTE.
(inhales)
THAT'S AWESOME.
HANG IT FOR THREE DAYS?
CORRECT.
SO THIS ONE
YOU'VE DONE ALREADY.
BEEN HANGING
FOR THREE DAYS.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
CUT A COUPLE
NICE BIG--
WHOA! SERIOUSLY?
IF YOU'RE GONNA
GET FOIE GRAS,
YOU SHOULD KNOW YOU'RE EATING
FOIE GRAS, YOU KNOW?
A LITTLE BIT OF TOASTED BRIOCHE
HERE FROM A LOCAL BAKERY.
PEACH MARMALADE,
A LITTLE QUENELLE DOLLOP OF THAT
ON THE PLATE,
AND SOME SEA SALT.
THAT LOOKS
TOO GOOD TO EAT.
WAIT TILL YOU EAT IT.
WOW.
MMM. I MEAN,
JUST MELTS IN YOUR MOUTH,
AND LOOK AT THAT--
LOOK HOW NICE IT CUTS.
MMM.
IT'S SO RICH,
SO FLAVORFUL,
AND SO IN BALANCE
WITH THE JAM.
MMM. I DON'T WANT TO USE
THE WORD "DELECTABLE,"
BUT IT'S--IT'S DECADENT.
IT HAS JUST SUCH RICHNESS
AND SUCH--SUCH APPRECIATION
FOR ALL THE WORK
THAT YOU PUT THROUGH.
MMM, AWESOME.
(man) FOIE GRAS WITH
SOUTH CAROLINA PEACH MARMALADE.
IT'S A NICE COMBINATION OF,
YOU KNOW, THE FATTY FOIE GRAS
WITH THE SWEETNESS OF THE
SOUTH CAROLINA PEACH MARMALADE.
WITH THE CRUNCH OF THE BRIOCHE,
IT JUST MAKES
A PERFECT COMBINATION.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THE FOOD HERE?
FIVE STARS.
FIVE STARS?
YEAH.
I'M GONNA KEEP ASKING YOU
ALL THESE QUESTIONS
UNTIL I EAT ALL THESE--
YOU KNOW THAT.
HOW MUCH OF THIS IS A JOB,
AND HOW MUCH OF THIS IS JUST
YOUR LOVE OF--OF FOOD?
I'D SAY 95% LOVE.
IT SHOWS, MAN.
WHAT A BLAST.
THANK YOU.
THANKS.
SO THAT'S IT FOR THIS TRIP,
BUT DON'T WORRY,
THERE'S PLENTY MORE TRIPLE "D"
JOINTS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
I'LL BE LOOKING
FOR YOU NEXT WEEK
ON
"DINERS, DRIVE-INS AND DIVES."
IT LOOKS LIKE IT'S
A FAKE MOVIE SET BACK THERE
WITH THE RAIN COMING
RIGHT DOWN THE WINDOW,
BUT IT IS COMING DOWN!
BEAUTIFUL DAY
IN NAGS HEAD.
IS THAT MY CAR
FLOATING AWAY?
(laughs)