Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow.
...we're pairing up
with a combo...
Hit it.
...of very unlikely partners.
It's
that kind of fantastic.
In Koreatown, Los Angeles...
Seriously.
...a craft-beer joint
with a gourmet-food flip...
Can you feel
the magic?
...that's doing
the Death by Duck dance.
This dude has duck gone wild
times two.
In Toronto, Canada...
Freedom toast.
...the 24-hour retro diner...
That's awesome.
...getting a big-time upgrade
on grilled cheese...
Three sandwiches is not normal.
This is crazy!
...apple pie a la mode...
It tastes like...
liquid apple pie.
...and even
the chicken sandwich.
It's the keyboard
in flavor town.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in Los Angeles
in Koreatown.
Now, I'm gonna check out a joint
that has no Korean food
on the menu,
and the name of it?
Well, it sounds like it's owned
by a couple
of fraternity brothers.
This is Beer Belly.
WAITER:
Some pork-belly chips.
We're all here
for the same reason.
Good drinks and good eats
all the time in here.
Can't beat it.
MAN: What first brought me
and most people here
was their beer selection.
FIERI: A rotating line-up
of local craft beers
that owner Jimmy Han
obsesses over.
Smog City XPA.
I loved beer so much
that I wanted to bring
craft beer into Koreatown.
That's just what he and his
wife, Yume, did back in 2011.
And they named the joint
after a condition
they obviously know
little about.
But no beer belly at all.
When we started Beer Belly,
it was all about the beer,
but we got so blessed
with Chef Wes.
He's just blown my mind.
That'd be Philly-transplant
Wes Lieberher.
Four minutes
on the Brussels sprouts.
He brings his own kind of flare
to regular food.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
I love
the duck-fat fries.
HAN: Death by Duck.
It's a bucket of fries
fried in duck fat.
Very, very good. It's
a shredded duck confit on top.
All right.
You are the Duckinator.
I am the Duckinator.
So, give me the rundown.
Okay, this duck is gonna be used
for two dishes.
One's the Death by Duck.
We're gonna use the legs, wings,
and necks for confit.
We're gonna use the breasts
for the Duck French Dip,
the skin
for duck-skin cracklins.
We're making
duck chicharrónes?
Yes, sir.
FIERI: A duck version
of deep-fried pork rinds?
Yeah, I'm onboard.
All right. Well,
let's break down the duck.
All right. We're gonna take our
whole duck. Here's the breast.
Now we're gonna remove the skin,
reserve the breasts.
The legs, the wings
are gonna go to confit,
because that's when you'll get
the awesome shred-off meat.
Yeah.
We're gonna take
our skin, too,
and throw it in this pot,
render it down.
Nice and slow on that?
Yeah.
We'll let that sit
for 40 minutes. Salt this.
You salt it
before you confit it?
Yes.
We cure them overnight.
All right. So, this has sat
for 24 hours.
We're gonna put it in our pan,
and then we're gonna take
this big old pot of rendered fat
and just pour it all over this.
Now the fat comes.
Cover this with foil,
pop it in the oven...
About four hours --
350°, 400°.
The chicharrónes
have rendered down.
We're gonna take this
over to the fryer and
we're gonna drop it in.
Hit the fryer at 350°,
make the chicharrónes.
And while that's frying up,
it's time for some sweet
and spicy dipping sauce.
Okay,
so what do you have here?
Okay, we got
our fresh raspberries
cooked down
with some sugar.
We're gonna put it
through this strainer here
just to get the seeds out.
And the ratio of raspberries
to sugar was...
Three to one.
I like it.
Now we're gonna add
our whole-grain mustard.
Mmm.
About half of this.
Stir it together.
Delicious.
Our fries are cooked.
We're gonna get
our Death by Duck plated.
Toss these fries with
a little bit of kosher salt,
some smoked salt --
It tastes like a campfire --
and then
sweet-onion sugar.
I like
the sugar component to it.
Then we're gonna toss our fries
in some rendered duck fat.
Seriously?
Yes, sir.
Throw these fries
in the bucket here.
It's not over yet.
More?
Now we're gonna take
our chicharrónes, chop these up.
A little salt on those.
Dude.
We're gonna put that
on top of there.
Now we're gonna take some meat
off this thigh over here.
That's
also gonna go on here?
Yes.
I'm out of here.
[ Chuckles ]
You get your side
of raspberry mustard.
And that's it.
Oh. Fries are cooked crispy,
tossed in duck fat.
The fries were enough.
Then you have to go
and chicharrón the duck skin.
You got that crunchy
greatness on there.
That was pretty ridiculous.
This dipping sauce --
bananas.
And you put
awesome duck on top.
Mmm. It's
so ducking delicious, man.
That's a meal in itself.
Sometimes you just say,
"Duck it."
That should be a t-shirt
around here.
[ Laughs ]
Awesome job.
Thank you.
LIEBERHER:
Death by Duck -- sell it.
That's very ducky. It has
that really strong duck flavor.
It goes great with the fries,
'cause they're so soft,
and it puts them together.
MAN: And then you've got
this raspberry mustard sauce.
Kind of cuts
through that fattiness almost
and balances that
really well.
Beer Belly
Grilled Cheese.
Thank you very much.
You start eating
and you just can't stop.
LIEBERHER:
Pizza Mac -- selling it.
Great food, great beers --
they keep changing their kegs,
so if you stay long enough,
they'll change it
and do something brand new.
I really work hard
to search out
and get the quality
local craft breweries.
We support our breweries.
White Dog IPA.
Every visit
is 10 new beers to try.
They really have
some excellent choices.
Craft beer and the duck-fat
fries, and I was hooked.
You have duck how many ways
on your menu?
Three or four.
FIERI: Including
this full-blown sandwich
that's duck gone wild
from tip to tail.
Duck French Dip.
Loaded with duck --
fantastic.
So,
what are we gonna make?
All right.
We're gonna take
our duck carcasses here,
and we're gonna make
duck stock.
Hit it.
We're gonna salt and pepper
them, roast them.
This is where it all comes
from -- the carcass, the bones.
Really bring out
that flavor.
Yep.
Now we're gonna season
the duck breasts.
This is
for the Duck French Dip.
Got the salt on the there,
black pepper, and sage.
Fresh sage?
Fresh.
Are we flipping them?
Yes.
There we go.
There you go.
Can you feel the magic?
Need more salt?
Yeah.
And then we're gonna toss those
in the oven.
In the oven, 350°?
These actually go in
at 500°.
Oh, so you're really
just gonna sear them off?
Yeah.
And we're only gonna roast them
for about eight minutes.
They need to be
still medium-rare to rare.
Awesome.
On to the next step.
All right.
This is our roasted duck jus.
And the mirepoix
with the roasted dark carcasses.
Cooked down for a couple hours
and strained out.
Now we just have our little
salt there, some butter,
and we're
gonna let that go.
Beautiful.
All right.
This is our duck breast.
We're gonna slice this down
nice and thin.
Nice and medium-rare
on that. Super tender.
We got our toasted French bun
here.
This is the fried duck-skin
horseradish.
The chicharrón aioli.
Slather that on there.
And our jus's just about ready.
We're gonna toss in
our duck here.
Just enough
to warm it up.
Good to go now.
That may look like
it's been cooked to well-done,
but it hasn't.
It's still super tender.
Shredded provolone on top.
Throw this bad boy
in the Salamander,
just melt the cheese down.
Tell me
about these pickled onions.
House-pickled shallots --
just red-wine vinegar and sugar.
Well, you got a shallot.
And shallots, too.
You miss those key points.
We're almost done here.
Got our provolone melted
on top.
You can throw that on there.
You're good.
And then our leftover jus.
Got to be kidding me.
We got to cut this monster,
if you don't mind.
Look at this.
Mmm.
Sop it up.
In the world of great duck
sandwiches that I've had --
duck dishes --
that's easily in the top-five,
all-time of my life.
Thank you.
It's tender. It's rich.
It's balanced.
Duck chicharrón aioli.
It's
that kind of fantastic.
This duck's good luck.
It's outrageous.
Mmm.
Out of bounds.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Duck French Dip.
There you go.
A lot of duck meat in there.
Very moist. Very good.
The au jus is fantastic.
I've maybe eaten duck
a few times in my life
before I came here,
and now I'm a big fan.
LIEBERHER:
Honey cilantro wings.
The food is to die for.
Completely real deal.
It's why I'm here
for six hours at a time.
This dude has duck gone wild
times two.
When we come back,
he's gonna make another dish.
Can we have some chicken?
We're gonna have
some chicken.
Welcome back to
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
in Los Angeles.
Not just Los Angeles,
but Koreatown.
Hanging out with Chef Wes.
Now, we have just done duck
two amazing ways,
and now he promised
no more duck.
We're gonna do...
Chicken wings.
They're something
that people always order
when they come here -- is wings.
They're
always a little bit different.
Not just chicken wings,
but...
Volcano Chipotle
Chicken Wings.
So, those will be
nice and mild.
MAN: Nothing better than having
a platter of chicken wings
in the middle of the table
and sharing with your friends.
They are my favorite wings.
It's hot. It's hot.
All right. We're gonna make
the Volcano Chipotle Wing sauce.
Hit it.
All right.
We're gonna start
with some ketchup.
Okay.
Pureed and strained
chipotle peppers.
Re-hydrated in adobo.
Yes.
[ Boston accent ]
Worcestershire sauce.
Worcestershire.
[ Normal voice ] I have
a lot of friends in Boston.
Okay.
They made sure
I knew how to say that.
Apple-cider vinegar.
A little sriracha?
Little sriracha.
This is Tabasco.
Liquid smoke?
This is
applewood liquid smoke.
I can smell it from here.
Brown sugar, kosher salt.
Whoa.
A little bit
of chili flake.
Put that in there.
Granulated garlic,
cayenne pepper.
What?!
Just a little.
And whole-grain mustard.
And that's it.
We give that a stir
and cook it down.
I put this
on a lot of stuff.
It does go great
with the wings.
So, the sauce is made.
Now...
We can start
our blue-cheese dressing here.
We've got
our house-made aioli.
You make the aioli
yourself?
Yes.
Sour cream, rice-wine vinegar,
lemon juice.
Gotcha.
Whisk this up. Add some salt
and our blue cheese.
We let this set up a little bit,
and then that is
what gets served alongside
these Volcano Wings?
Absolutely.
Word.
Okay.
Let's do the wings.
Mmm. That's the way I like them.
Hot.
This is our finished
Chipotle Volcano sauce.
Ooh, it's like wall paste.
It's
all about the sauce.
All right.
We're gonna plate these up.
We're done.
All right, my home chicken.
All right.
Smells spicy.
[ Coughs ]
Wow.
Man, those are hot.
Mmm.
So, they're spicy, not overly
spicy, a little bit of sweet.
The sauce glazes on
really nice. Mmm.
I love the chipotle
in there
and a little bit of that
liquid smoke coming through.
The wings are cooked perfectly,
and I mean perfectly.
And the blue cheese
is ridiculous.
Awesome.
LIEBERHER:
Volcano Chipotle Wings.
They're great
because they come on with a bang
and then the heat
really starts to sear.
There's also so much flavor
going on,
and the fact that they're
so tender and so moist --
They're
so good to eat.
Chicken and Waffle.
I don't consider myself a
foodie, but I like quality food,
and that's what I get here.
It's a blend of everything
that you ever want --
good, American,
hearty comfort food.
This is where it's at.
Without question,
Philadelphia's got to miss you.
California's
lucky to have you.
Thank you.
I'll be back.
This is the duck master.
FIERI: Up next...
I mean, it's the crunchy
everybody's trying to achieve.
We're headed to Toronto, Canada,
where an old-school diner...
Really?
Yep.
...is getting a serious makeover
in the kitchen.
We're gonna take the apple pie
and...
Make a milkshake.
'Cause that's
what everybody does.
You know,
when I say, "old-school diner,"
I know you think
it's got to be in New Jersey.
Well, this joint -- It's
80 years old and guess what.
It's not in New Jersey.
Matter of fact, it's not even
in the United States.
It's here in Toronto, Canada.
This is the Lakeview Restaurant.
BOUY: One Lakeview Burger
with sweet fry in the window.
WOMAN: You feel like
you're walking back in time.
You're in the 1950's
or something,
like you're watching
an old movie.
One Pulled Pork Sandwich
with fries in the window.
It's that vintage vibe that
this neighborhood really loves.
FIERI:
The throwback that was brought
back to its former glory
in 2008 when
Alex Sengupta and his partners
picked up this Toronto landmark.
How do you describe
what this is?
Gourmet 24-hour diner.
WOMAN: There's a classic,
nostalgic feel to this place.
They have amazing food here.
FIERI: And that
is James Bouy's department.
Everything's house-made here --
absolutely everything.
Every dressing, burgers,
everything's homemade.
We just
revamped the whole menu.
Went back
to, sort of, the basics.
While adding a little bit of
their own somethin' somethin'.
They've got some
different twists on the food.
With the Freedom Toast.
FIERI: A north-of-the-border
speciality.
WOMAN:
It's Stuffed French Toast,
so it's egg-battered bread
stuffed with peameal bacon --
FIERI: Say what?
Peameal?
Peameal.
It's like Canadian bacon.
It's just cured
and rolled in cornmeal.
Give me the rundown.
So, we got our Havarti.
Just gonna cut that.
And then our brie.
We're ready to build.
So, we got three pieces down.
Put our brie on the bottom.
This is one meal?
This is one meal --
one dish.
And that's one peameal each?
That's one peameal.
And then our Havarti.
So, now we're gonna
dredge it in egg wash.
So,
it's a croque monsieur.
That's what we call,
in France,
when you would put
the Swiss and the ham
all together.
All right.
So, we're doing Freedom Toast.
Freedom Toast.
Baby greens,
our house honey balsamic,
some sunflower seeds
on top,
house-cut home fries
seasoned with cumin,
Cajun spice, and salt.
Now we have
our Freedom Toast.
Our melons.
That's it. Freedom Toast.
Just so you understand,
to the rest of the world,
three sandwiches is not normal.
This is crazy.
You have to
dip it in the syrup.
You dip this in the syrup?
Correct.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, we'll just try it
Freedom first.
The, uh, ham...
What do you think?
I think it's great.
I love brie cheese.
That works out perfect.
It's always a party
when you have Havarti,
and the chips
you make yourself?
Yep.
What do you call these?
Home fries.
You serve those
for breakfast?
Correct.
Tasty.
I like it
with the cumin on there.
I like that you take
so much time and care in it.
Making the chips --
and to see that
you guys take the time
to make the dressing --
little things like that --
making everything yourself --
impressive.
Nice job.
[ Laughs ]
I love the balance
of sweet and savory.
The peameal bacon
gives a little punch to it.
This is my go-to dish
when I come here.
People have been coming here
for decades.
The son
of the original owner's here.
Right at the bar there.
Sir, rumor has it that
your dad started this joint.
Yes,
with two of his partners.
FIERI: And not a lot
has changed since then.
MAN: There's all these, like,
fridges and stuff
that are old school
and that woodwork in here --
It's totally unique in the city.
And this is still so old school
that if you look, like,
this is where the cigarettes
used to be stacked up.
I mean, this is all original
cabinetry and the whole thing.
Yeah, yeah.
That's awesome.
They kept the menu in a classic
state of mind, as well.
BOUY: Corn Flake Chicken Club's
in the window.
You're going to
Lakeview Restaurant,
you got to have
the Corn Flake Chicken?
That's right.
Really?
Yeah.
MAN:
Three-piece Corn Flake Club.
Well, give me the rundown.
Crush up our Corn Flakes.
I'm just gonna
fillet the chicken.
White breast meat.
Trim off the fat
and then just fillet her.
And we're just gonna go Corn
Flakes directly to the chicken?
No, it's gonna go
into seasoned flour.
A little garlic powder,
a little black pepper,
and a little bit of salt.
Mix her up.
You want this egg wash?
Please.
Ooh,
just dare me to chuck it.
Okay, so, into the flour.
Into the egg wash.
This has got to be
super crunchy.
It is.
And that's just gonna make
this crunchalicious chicken.
So, the chicken goes down
and fries at 350°
for how many minutes?
About three -- three to four.
Corn Flake Chicken
Clubhouse stack.
Sweet chili mayo on all three
of them -- lots of it.
[ Whistles ]
Green leaf lettuce on one layer
and our Corn Flake Chicken.
Another piece of bread.
Tomatoes and our bacon.
And skewer it,
cut that in half.
House-cut fries?
Yes, sir.
And then our clubhouse.
It's the keyboard
in flavor town.
[ Piano riff plays ]
Look at the size of this.
You can do it.
[ Crunches ]
[ Mumbles ]
Toasting the bread nice,
having a little spicy mayo
is key,
but what so makes it
is that crunchy chicken.
Mm-hmm.
I mean,
here's the thing.
Club sandwich
is a club sandwich,
but if you're gonna have it
on your menu
and you're gonna make it
a specialty item,
do something funky with it.
And I will say that breading it
in cereal -- pretty funky.
That was
an awesome crunch.
I mean, it's the crunch that
everybody's trying to achieve
when they bread something
and fry it.
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
It's a really good,
classic club.
Nice, juicy chicken.
Just the crunch
of the Corn Flakes
really hits the spot.
Kind of cool thing that
you can only really get here.
What are we making next?
The Apple Pie Milkshake.
Homemade apple pie
into a milkshake.
Oh, that's gonna be good.
It's killer.
So, welcome back.
We're at Lakeview Restaurant
in Toronto, Canada --
a classic diner
that's been around since 1932.
Mac and cheese going up.
Table two.
It is 24-hours?
24-hours.
So, we get a lot of late-night
crowd after the bar rush.
So, anything goes
from full-on breakfast...
BOUY: One Disco Breakfast
in the window.
...to late-night cravings
like candy bars
hot from the fryer
or even -- get this --
pie in the a la mode.
WOMAN: I would never consider
throwing a piece of pie
into my milkshake,
so it's pretty unique that way.
Enjoy.
This is a filling
to make the apple pie
that's gonna
turn into a milkshake.
Hit it.
So, just
our Granny Smith apples
and some butter in there.
I always like that tartness
of the Granny Smith apple
with apple pie.
We go brown sugar, flour, sugar,
nutmeg, a little salt --
Cinnaminaminamin.
You got it.
Very nice.
Just gonna mix her up.
And that's the filling.
You got it.
We add our filling.
That's our apple pie,
then we have a cover for it.
375° -- 40 minutes.
Correct.
Let it cool.
We're gonna take the apple pie
and...
Make a milkshake.
'Cause
that's what everybody does.
Come on, let's do this.
All right.
So...
You guys
make a lot of milkshakes.
We do. Yeah.
So,
we got two and a half,
three scoops
of French vanilla ice cream.
I'm adding whole milk --
probably about
a cup and a half to two cups.
Canadian rye is really good
in these, as well.
Yeah, I bet it is.
You take a piece of pie
and chop that up a little.
Put that in there.
Nice and full.
And 'cause we make
a variety of different pies,
obviously,
the apple is the favorite.
Right.
How's that mincemeat go?
[ Chuckles ]
Mincemeat milkshake.
We get all the apple chunks
in there.
FIERI: Oh.
It stays nice and chunky
in the glass.
And then what we do
is we take a piece of the crust
right on top there for you.
Mmm.
It tastes like...
like liquid apple pie.
That's awesome.
I love the crust in there.
Mmm. That's good.
Here's
your Apple Pie Milkshake.
It's pretty amazing.
There's all kinds of, like,
nice chunks of apple in here,
little bits of crust --
a nice surprise.
It's not like any other
milkshake I've ever had.
Good, honest food.
And they do everything
very well.
BOUY:
Pulled Pork, fries, salad.
You absolutely have to stop
at the Lakeview Restaurant.
FIERI: It's in great condition,
has good energy,
really nice people working here,
awesome place.
Thanks for having us.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughter ]
You know, this is the problem --
is I try
to look back at the camera,
and I got the cackle-giggle kids
over here.
[ Clears throat ]
That was really good.
[ Laughter ]