Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Blender whirs ]
...it's all about
scratch-made success.
Hey, it's Brooklyn.
Everything goes here.
Hey!
In Brooklyn, New York,
right under
the Williamsburg Bridge,
a southern-comfort stand...
Here at the Pies N' Thighs
Health Center.
...pulling pork...
[ As Michael Jackson ]
Whoo-hoo.
...frying chicken...
[ Normal voice ] That's good
fried chicken.
...and turning out
big-time doughnuts...
You have got to
be kidding me.
This thing weighs
like three pounds.
...and in Puyallup,
Washington...
Seriously?
Didn't see that coming.
...the former feed store
that's back in business...
Mmm.
You're not sharin'?
Here's the deal --
My name's not Sharon.
It's Guy, Guy Fieri.
...rolling out
million-dollar meatballs...
Looks good
from over here.
...and a Sloppy Joe
made by mama.
Who's ever mom
made this,
she's the mom,
the bomb dot com.
Yeah!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You know,
the greater New York area
has one of the most eclectic mix
of foods you can find anywhere.
I mean, you name it,
they got it.
So, when you're rolling
out of Manhattan
over the Williamsburg Bridge,
you can expect to find some --
Hold it. Hold it.
Exactly --
some good-old Southern food
with a twist.
This is Pies 'n' Thighs.
BANE: Pulled pork
and baked beans.
What they're doing is amazing.
BANE:
Chicken and waffles.
Hey, it's Brooklyn.
Everything goes here.
Hey!
FIERI: Just ask the president
of Brooklyn, Marty Markowitz.
So many of the innovative chefs
have set up shop right here,
like Pies 'n' Thighs.
And for the record,
this place has three of them --
Sarah Sanneh, Carolyn Bane,
and Erika Geldzahler.
You got
a food-school graduate,
a culinary-school
graduate,
and a...
Crimson. Go Crimson.
Harvard graduate.
...and a Harvard
graduate.
How long you been
in business together?
Six years.
How do you describe
the food?
Classic American with
a strong southern influence.
The best biscuits
in the country.
My favorite pulled-pork sandwich
in New York.
What are we
gonna make?
We are seasoning
this pork shoulder
for the pork sandwich.
Start off
with the dry rub.
Paprika.
Cayenne.
Whoa!
Yeah,
it's gonna be hot.
Oh, really?
Brown sugar.
Black pepper.
Kosher salt.
We got our rub.
Right.
One second.
What are you doing?
I have a little sink
under here.
[ High-pitched voice ]
Hello!
[ Chuckles ]
[ Normal voice ]
That's awesome.
What other
little mystery items
do you guys have
around here?
I want to go downstairs
and get something.
We might have
a couple secret doors.
[ Laughter ]
Yeah, that.
I season the pork with salt,
pat the spice mixture.
This an M.J. thing you got going
right now -- one glove?
[ As Michael Jackson ]
Whoo-hoo.
Aah.
[ Laughter ]
[ Normal voice ] All right,
let's go to the smoker.
[ Normal voice ]
I should have.
[ Laughter ]
We're gonna smoke it
at 200 degrees
for 9 to 10 hours.
Ready.
Let's see it.
All right. 'Cause I'm just
taking them out really gently.
We're gonna shred it
for serving.
We're gonna shred it?
This is the good stuff.
These are the drippings.
Wow.
Yeah.
Marinate
the pulled pork.
So, we're gonna
make the pork sandwich.
Okay.
Coleslaw.
Wow.
Classic pickle.
Get the pork
on there.
A little
peppered vinegar.
Oh, Carolina style!
I'll put it together
for you.
Oh, not over smoked,
not overdone.
Pork's super tender --
nice bark, nice crust.
Not pulled too thin so you still
get some really good texture,
and that vinegar
with the pepper at the end --
dynamite.
Real deal.
Thank you.
I'm impressed.
BANE:
Pulled-pork sandwich.
The flavor's fantastic...
I love how the bottom
of the biscuit gets soggy.
By the end of the thing,
you're kind of --
you switch over
to fork and knife.
Yeah.
...and the pies --
out of this world.
FIERI: And what they're doing
with pies,
they're doing with thighs.
This is the best chicken
you're gonna get in New York.
FIERI: On a plate --
a biscuit, or a waffle.
BANE:
Chicken and waffles.
If you're here,
you must try this dish.
We're gonna make our seasoning
for the chicken.
No salt?
That's gonna be
in the brine.
We're seasoning it first
then brining it?
It's another --
Hang on.
We do it this way.
I think it really sticks
to the skin.
You're gonna see.
You're gonna taste it.
All right. All right.
It's gonna be good.
So, I'm adding paprika.
Copious amounts
of cayenne again?
Ground black pepper.
Get a little bit
on all sides...
...and then we're just
gonna cover it
with the sugar
and salt brine.
How long
we gonna brine this?
24 hours.
Now into the...
Into
the all-purpose flour.
Just flour?
We're gonna shake it up
and take it to the fryer.
I will forewarn you...
We're gonna need
a bigger waffle maker.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Just load it up with
our buckwheat waffle batter.
You just glop it in there.
Let me get you a snow shovel.
Okay,
our waffles are ready.
My cutting board.
Okay.
Cinnamon butter.
Blueberry compote,
and this is just
fresh blueberries lightly cooked
with a little bit of sugar.
And that's
all she wrote?
Chicken and waffles.
Not oily at all,
not too heavily battered.
This is
good fried chicken.
Thank you.
When the chicken
is this tender,
you get all of that fry
coming with it,
that's crunchification
right there.
[ With mouth full ]
I'm gonna dig over here.
Uh...
[ Chuckles ]
I have to say that that
is the most savory combination
of chicken and waffles
I've had.
That's good fried chicken.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Chicken and waffles.
That crust is so sweet,
and the chicken is so tender.
On par, if not better than what
my grandmother used to make.
The waffles -- wow.
Amazing.
Not that I can eat any more,
but what are we gonna make next?
One of
our signature doughnuts.
Which one's that gonna be?
No, don't tell us.
You got to come back
and see.
We're at Pies 'n' Thighs
in Brooklyn.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
So, here we are.
"Triple D"
rolls into Brooklyn,
and we're at Pies 'n' Thighs...
and doughnuts.
FIERI: Okay, well,
maybe not the doughnut part,
but from what folks
are telling me, it should be.
Well, I'm a big fan
of doughnuts.
FIERI:
And so is this guy --
Brooklyn president
Marty Markowitz,
and if he likes them,
well, I guess I got to try one.
BANE:
Pecan crunch doughnut.
Now what are we making?
We're making toffy,
and it's part of the pecan
butter-crunch doughnut.
Here at the Pies 'n' Thighs
Health Center.
Two pounds of butter.
A quart of sugar.
So, we're really just
gonna let this cook.
You got to
caramelize the sugar.
Mm-hmm.
Stir constantly
so no lumps form.
We'll
stir, stir, stir,
it will turn
a beautiful golden brown...
...and then we'll pour it out
and let it harden.
And that's the toffy?
Next up.
We are making our dough
for doughnuts.
How do we start it?
Sugar.
Milk.
Egg yolks.
Whole eggs.
Yeast.
Bread flour.
Salt
and shortening,
and mix them on medium speed
for 10 minutes.
Wow,
and that's it?
It's pretty easy.
We are ready to roll out
our dough for doughnuts.
I'm gonna turn this over
and let this fall out.
Wait, wait, wait.
Sorry.
[ Vocalizes
squishing ]
That's the noise
it made.
So, we're just
letting it fall
so that we're handling it
as little as possible.
Kind of like
the biscuit theory?
Yeah.
Pat this out just a little bit
to get the shape.
So, you were
so delicate
you couldn't
take it out of the bin,
but now
you just knuckle it.
Now I'm ready.
And then we're gonna
roll it out.
All right,
this is a beautiful dough.
That's
a doughnut cutter.
So getting
one of these.
Yeah.
That's cool.
We're cutting our doughnuts
with a little bit of force.
Are we gonna
let these rise?
Yeah, we'll let them
pretty much double --
about 45 minutes.
So, this is what they're like --
no skins, still nice and tender.
Really soft.
Really soft,
and they're gonna go in --
not the chicken fryer.
No, they're gonna
go in the small fryer.
I'll hold them for you.
What temperature?
325.
Do we have to
flip them?
We will after
two and a half minutes.
I smell the --
I want to say yeast.
I mean,
you can smell the yeast
kind of like
when bread's baking.
Oh!
Yeah.
Can I hold?
Sure.
Okay.
Over here.
The toffy's cooled.
Oh, we just --
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
Like an animal,
you're just breaking it up
in pieces.
Yeah.
Into the robo.
Got a good, nice,
little nuttiness to it.
Already ground up
the pecan pieces.
We're gonna put them
in about equal parts.
50-50?
Yeah.
Toss this up
a little.
This is the glaze?
Yeah.
What do we have here
for glaze?
Confectioner sugar
and a little bit of milk.
That's it.
Whoa.
9 out of 10 dentists --
Recommend.
You'd be surprised.
[ Whistles ]
Roll them around.
There you got it.
Holy -- you got to be
kidding me.
Man, I got to do this.
And I don't even --
I'm not even.
Yeah.
I mean, it's gonna get
in my bling.
This thing weighs
like three pounds.
It's lunch.
Is there any on my face.
Just a little bit.
No?
No one will notice.
That's awesome, though.
Cool.
The fact that you made
the doughnut, put it together,
serve it up as a three-pound
lunch for nine,
it's awesome.
I love coming here.
You're gonna leave
full and happy.
I mean, look at this.
Oh, I'm looking at it.
Believe me.
Look -- look at this.
You have put on five pounds
looking at that thing.
That's like a three-pound
doughnut for two bucks.
Oh, yes.
You want some pie,
you want some thigh,
or you want
some doughnuts?
Taking some key lime pie
to the office.
I just lost him
in the interview.
He's off to pie
and doughnut land.
FIERI: Up next...
Arms up, loosening the neck,
rotating.
We're heading
to Puyallup, Washington,
for a meat-lover's
smorgasbord...
These are $95 meatballs.
...with my kind
of vegetable side.
I'm an
artichoke-eating machine.
I'm about 10 miles southeast of
Tacoma, Washington, in Puyallup.
Now, as most of you know,
it's home to the Puyallup Fair,
one of the top-10 fairs
in the country.
But for me, I'm here for a
funky, little "Triple D" joint.
It was once a feed store,
then an antique shop,
and now it's
Crockett's Public House.
Mom's Sloppy Joe coming up.
I actually eat here more
than I probably eat at home.
It's just all from scratch.
This is the place?
This is the place.
Whoo!
FIERI: Dreamt up and built up
by owner Shaun Brobak.
I'm a career restaurant guy.
Who got his start
washing dishes at age 16.
I practiced and got experience
on everybody else's restaurants.
Smartest thing in the world
you can do.
And he found a kindred spirit
in Chef Brian Johnston.
I started out
washing dishes.
Really cool chef
gave me a shot.
Now a couple of guys
who came through the ranks
are dropping culinary bombs
on the peep's of Puyallup.
Like this mesquite-smoked,
peel-away piece of heaven.
Fire-grilled artichokes up.
Artichoke is, like,
one of a kind.
That's a monster.
Give me the break-down.
You want to take
the bottom leaves off.
A little bit tougher.
We're gonna peel the bottom
leaves and the stem.
You start seeing just the white
part in the middle.
It's real tender.
Tender meat, kind of like
the heart of the artichoke.
Then we're gonna want
to cut it in half
right down the middle
of the stem.
Got it.
So, get it cut in half.
Look at that, huh?
We're gonna dig out
all the fibers on the inside
right down to the bottom
of the artichoke.
And then they go
straight in the boiling water.
Is the water salted?
Salted, yes.
Okay, so, we let these go
for 10 minutes,
pull them out,
hit them in an ice bath.
Yep.
Now we're gonna make
the Calabrian aioli.
From Calabria,
the peppers.
Mm-hmm.
And you want to take
the seeds out of them first.
Seeds and stems are off.
The lemon juice.
And we have
some Dijon mustard.
Puree the pepper.
This is gonna
be strong, huh?
Probably a little spicy.
[ Whistles ]
All right, so,
we're gonna take this.
Now fold it into the mayo.
Yes.
Got it.
All right,
artichokes done.
The artichokes are ready.
Take them to the grill.
We got
the mesquite rolling.
We're gonna brush them with
a little bit of canola oil,
and we're gonna season them
with a little seasoning salt.
They go right on the fire.
Oh, that's nice.
Excellent.
Smell that mesquite.
Killer.
They're ready.
I'm an
artichoke-eating machine.
And then serve that
with the Calabrian aioli?
This is my favorite part --
getting right down here
to the heart of it.
Into a little bit
of that aioli.
Mmm. Nice and tender.
Just give it a little dip
right there.
Mmm.
And the kicker is that smoke
from the mesquite.
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm. Mmm!
I wish you would have made
some for yourself.
You're not sharin'?
Here's the deal.
My name's not Sharon.
It's Guy, Guy Fieri.
I don't think that we've
ever done roasted artichokes
on "Triple D."
And I don't think
I've ever had one of the chefs
call me Sharon.
Couple of firsts.
You're gonna love this.
Artichokes in the window.
I have never tasted anything
quite like this.
Nice flavor,
roasted just right.
Plating Flagship.
FIERI: And this joint's got
a menu with everything...
Colossal shrimp.
...but the kitchen sink.
St. Louis ribs
in the window.
And he's even turning
this classic Italian dish...
Public House meatballs.
...into a high-end, meaty feast.
Now we make
the meatballs?
Yep.
We've got
gelatin and water.
We're gonna bloom
the gelatin first.
It's gonna kind of hold
the meatballs together.
And we'll set that aside.
Then we're going
bread crumbs.
Buttermilk.
Incorporate all that fat
and a little bit of that tang.
Then we're just using
the egg yolk --
just for the richness.
Fresh garlic.
[ Whistles ]
Next, we use
the gelatin that we bloomed.
Get it mixed in
with the bread crumbs.
We've got
fresh ground pepper.
Cayenne pepper.
A little bit of heat.
White pepper.
Chili flakes.
Kosher salt.
Just get it all mixed in.
Next up, we're going
with ground veal.
Then we're going
with the Kurobuta pork.
Kurobuta pork.
So, you're talking, like,
the high end of pork.
And then we've got
fresh ground sirloin.
Big in flavor.
So, you're using
the big three,
which I think
is completely necessary.
But you're going
to the extreme.
And then
the prosciutto also.
Of course.
These are $95 meatballs.
[ Laughs ]
Mix that.
Now what would you
like me to do,
besides finish
the prosciutto?
Well,
if we have any left,
we're gonna put
the prosciutto in.
Uh-huh.
Mr. Funny-Funny.
[ Laughs ]
Got fresh chopped parsley.
Italian?
Yes.
Grated pecorino romano.
We're gonna mix
one more time.
So, now we're gonna
form the meatballs.
About four-and-a-half ounces.
Gonna roast these off
in the oven.
350.
20, 25 minutes.
Absolutely.
All right, man.
Meatballs are done?
Yep, meatballs done.
Okay, so, we've got
our marinara.
Three meatballs.
We're gonna go
chopped pistachios.
Seriously?
Didn't see that coming.
Grano Padano.
Parmesan cheese.
I like this move.
Fresh-grated lime zest.
Adds a nice,
little zing to it.
There we go.
This is gonna get messy.
Mmm, that's a really
tender meatball.
It's real traditional
in the way you made it,
using the three meats.
You add your own
little twist to it,
throwing these pistachios
on top.
Mmm, but the lime zest --
really key.
Needs a little more
prosciutto, though.
[ Laughs ]
Public House meatballs up.
These meatballs are amazing.
This is a wonderful treat
for a meal.
So, here's the deal.
We're hanging out in Puyallup,
at Crockett's,
right next to the train track,
with Captain Funny.
When we come back,
what are we gonna make next?
Mom's Sloppy Joe.
See you in a little bit.
[ Train horn blares ]
FIERI: We're back at Crockett's
Public House
in Puyallup, Washington...
Colossal shrimp up.
...where owner Shaun Brobak
turned an old feed store
into a killer pub.
Plating sloppy.
And Chef Brian Johnston is
taking an old diner classic...
WOMAN: Mom's Sloppy Joe.
...and giving it
just a little kick.
The flavor is just to die for.
Let's start it off.
Start with canola oil,
hot pan.
We're going
fresh ground sirloin.
Fresh ground Kurobuta pork.
Meat's browned.
We're gonna add
diced red onion
and diced red bell pepper.
We got fresh minced garlic,
some minced jalapeños.
And then we're gonna stir
and kind of let it cook
a little bit.
Next up?
We're gonna hit it
with some red wine.
Some red-wine vinegar.
And some
Worcestershire sauce.
Tomato sauce.
Tomato paste.
Dark brown sugar.
Dry mustard.
Cumin.
Cayenne pepper.
Paprika.
This is like speed sloppy.
Fresh black pepper
and kosher salt.
Mix it all up, let it cook down.
How long's this gonna cook?
This is gonna cook for about
a half hour, 40 minutes.
Ready?
I'm ready.
Okay.
We're gonna go
coleslaw first.
Then we got a sesame seed
brioche bun.
Get our hot
Sloppy Joe mix here.
[ Whistles ]
And it is sloppy.
A big pile of crispy,
fried onion rings.
Just get the bun
on the side.
And that's it.
Try to put that
in your mouth.
That's ridiculous.
You guys haven't seen the hunch
in a while, have you?
Arms up, loosening the neck,
rotating.
Oh, yeah.
In the world
of Sloppy Joes,
there has to be
some key pieces.
One, the tang.
You got to have
a little bit of heat --
not hot, but a little bit
of heat, a little bit of spice.
But the key important piece
is texture.
There's got to be
texture in the meat.
This has got
all those components.
And then the kicker,
get some of these
onion straws.
Great Sloppy Joe.
That is up there.
Who's ever mom made this,
she's the mom,
the bomb dot com.
Yeah!
Mom's Sloppy Joe coming up.
I don't know that I would have
driven to this little town
and thought I was gonna find
food like this.
But this is the kind of joint
we want on "Triple D."
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
All right, kids,
it's the game
everybody's playing
at home now --
is build that chicken.
It's a three-winged
chicken.
Uh-oh. [ Laughs ]