I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Be careful.
...I'm tossing caution
to the wind...
Oh, that's not
"Be careful."
That's
"You're gonna love it."
...for some
unexpected eats.
Whoo! Thanks for the warning
on that one!
In Philadelphia, Pennsylvania...
Now I know
you're serious.
[ Laughs ]
...the tap room
pioneering local brew...
Ho, ho, ho.
...and a chicken pie...
I'm dying to see
this inside here.
...minus the pot.
Oh, this is dreamy
and creamy.
In Tempe, Arizona...
This is
a flavor temple.
...a Pakistani joint...
Oh, I can't stop!
...teaching me the ways
of the tandoori.
This is out of bounds.
[ Chuckles ]
And in Denver, Colorado...
Gonna be butter,
baby.
...a retro pub...
Whoa!
...rockin' out
some killer short rib grub.
That's all going
on one?
PROUT: Nice, full meal
for you.
That burger
was nuts!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in the
Northern Liberties neighborhood
of Philadelphia, about
six blocks from Center City,
to check out a joint --
Now, get this.
They were the first to be
serving
only locally made drafts
in Philadelphia,
and maybe one of the first
in the country.
You think their beer program's
impressive?
Check out their menu.
This is Standard Tap.
This place is known
for phenomenal beer.
I didn't know it
for phenomenal food.
We're talking real food
that takes time to make,
that takes thought.
Grilled octopus
in the window.
What do you like more?
The beer selection or the food?
Beer I had first,
and then I come for the food.
FIERI:
Exactly how owners William Reed
and Paul Kimport like to eat.
It's more fun to eat
in a bar
than it is to drink
in a restaurant,
and that's
what our passion is,
is great local beer,
great local food.
FIERI: So, when they opened
the joint in '99,
they stuck with the beer,
and handed the food over
to friend and chef
Carolynn Angle.
How long
have you been here?
I've been here
for 13 years.
What, did you start here,
like,
on an 8th-grade field trip
and got lost?
[ Laughs ]
Something like that.
But the concept
isn't lost on Carolynn.
Everything she cooks
is so fresh and local,
they don't even print
a daily menu.
The menu changes, but they
always have the standards.
My dad makes great burgers,
but this is amazing.
I agree.
I concede.
Seems to be a little family feud
going on here.
I always fall back
on the chicken pie.
It's all crust.
It's amazing.
A chicken pie
in the window.
We're making
chicken pot pie?
Chicken pie.
Not pot pie.
Difference is
it's not in a pot.
It's molded.
We build it into pastry.
Just season them with salt and
pepper, and then we roast them.
Not gonna drizzle them
with anything --
we're just gonna roast them
right off in their own juices.
In the oven?
In the oven. 400.
A little over an hour.
[ Bell dings ]
So, chickens are cool?
Chickens are cool.
So, we're gonna pick 'em.
Are we saving the skin?
We're saving the skin.
We're gonna save the
bones and we're gonna
make a stock out of it.
No bones.
How did this get in there?
That wasn't me.
That was yours.
No, we -- I --
Nope,
that was yours.
Next step?
We're making the filling
for chicken pie.
Let's hit it.
Get the pan hot.
Blended oil.
Quartered
cremini mushrooms.
Chopped garlic.
Then you want to
sauté these
till they're
completely caramelized.
Add salt and pepper.
It's a pretty hearty
dish.
It's good drinking food.
Good drinking food.
We add some
fresh sage and thyme...
fresh parsley...
then you add
your mirepoix.
[ Whistles ]
Sweat it all down.
And then
we add the chicken.
Okay.
And then we add
the chicken stock.
Now, how long
will this cook down
once the stock goes in?
This will take
a couple hours.
Just let it reduce.
And at the end of it
cooking down,
what are we gonna do?
We're gonna add a roux,
and then we're gonna
slurry it into it.
We're gonna just add a little
bit in just to allow it --
So, that'll tighten
all the juices up.
Tighten it up,
but not too tight.
Now we're gonna
make the pie.
Then we cut
the pastry.
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
How much --
I wasn't trying to be
Santa Claus there.
How big is the filling
in this thing?
It's a little smaller
than a softball.
About that.
Would you like me to get on
the cutting side of this?
That'd be great.
Grab a pastry and you stretch it
over like that,
and then you cinch it.
Just stretch it -- You don't
want to tear the pastry.
Then it's
nice and sealed.
Take a piece
of puff pastry,
cut a strip, and just twist it
and put it right on top.
Doctor, how is one
twisting this?
Now, these are
baked order?
We parbake them.
Parbake them, hold them,
fire them off in the oven again.
Does it come with
a gravy or a sauce?
With a salad -- a bed of salad
underneath it.
And some
mustard vinaigrette.
Just a nice, little
bed of it.
There you go.
I'm dying to see
this inside here.
Oh, that's dreamy
and creamy.
Yeah.
All right.
I don't think most people
would anticipate
putting this
on top of a salad,
but you get a nice crunch,
you get that vinaigrette.
If you like
chicken pot pie
and you want more of the crunchy
crust that you have on top,
this is what you want.
That's killer.
Wait till you guys try this.
Tell me about
the chicken pie.
It's, like, super savory.
Tons of chicken.
WOMAN:
It's like a chicken soup
with a great pastry puff
outside of it.
MAN:
A lot of depth of flavor.
This is chicken pie
the way it should be.
These guys have been setting
the trend for a long time.
Really?
Yeah.
It's not your average,
you know, corner pub.
You're gonna find things
that are slightly unusual.
We're at the Standard Tap,
and when we come back,
we're gonna try...
O--
Don't -- Ah!
See you
in a little bit.
Don't you love
when I do that to you?
So, here we are --
Standard Tap in Philadelphia.
And Chef and I have had
a fantastic chicken pie.
Not chicken pot pie
because that comes in a...
Pot.
Thank you very much.
What are we on to now?
Drumroll.
Octopus.
Oh, really? You're gonna
give it out that quick?
Fire it up.
Octopus.
All right, first,
let's add some water.
Then you add
Spanish onions, celery...
fresh grapefruit...
oranges...
lemons...
garlic...
bay leaf...
fresh thyme,
and parsley.
We're gonna let this go
for a boil.
We're gonna add
the octopus.
All right, so, the octopus
is not gonna get any --
no salting, no tenderizing,
no nothing.
No, it's fresh octopus,
so it doesn't need it.
Nice.
We're going to...
We're going to make a marinade
for the octopus.
Start with some garlic.
Crushed red pepper.
Oh!
Little bit of celery seed.
Fresh parsley.
What's up with the red chili
flake there, sunshine?
Got to get some heat.
Got some fresh thyme
and oregano,
a little salt,
white pepper...
vinegar...
lemon juice...
olive oil,
blend, and whisk.
The octopus
is gonna go down.
Are we gonna cut it
before we drop it in?
We're gonna pull it apart
with our hands.
Tear it apart.
Now I know
you're serious.
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
We done?
We're done.
So, how long
was this down?
A couple hours.
Just till it's --
I mean, it literally is
fall-apart tender.
So, you just
tear it apart.
You leave the suckers on,
and you throw it in there.
Marinade up. And then, are we
gonna grill it for service?
We're gonna grill it
for service.
Caramelize the octopus.
Pretty good.
Ready to rock?
Ready to go.
Take that one.
Some head on there.
Just put a little bit
of baby greens,
some arugula,
and some tatsoi,
and that's an oregano
potato salad.
A little bit
of olive oil.
A little bit of lemon.
A wedge.
Fresh parsley.
That's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
Mmm.
That's good.
It's not so cooked down
that it's falling apart
or it's dry.
Dynamite.
Mmm. Not enough people
try octopus.
Really nice job.
I don't always order octopus,
but this is phenomenal.
MAN:
Sometimes you run into places
where they take off
the suction cups.
I love how they
leave it on here.
It adds a little extra
little crunchiness.
It is truly outstanding.
So, this is a normal kind of
joint you'd find in Philly?
No, it's
extraordinary.
WOMAN: It's the anchor
of the neighborhood.
You got to come down
and try Standard Tap.
Out of bounds --
great beer, killer food.
FIERI: Coming up --
We're headed
to Tempe, Arizona, man...
Thanks for the warning
on that one!
...for, what else,
but real-deal Pakistani!
Are you supposed to
eat this by hand?
No, you can use
a fork.
Now you tell me.
Yeah.
I'm here in Tempe, Arizona,
right across the street
from Arizona State,
home of the Sun Devils,
to check out some food
you'd expect in Arizona --
Mexican.
I'm here at Los --
No...
Dos --
Oh, no, that's
a different place!
I'm here to check out
some Pakistani food
at this joint,
the Curry Corner.
Goat karahi.
MAN: It's a gem -- I would've
never expected to find
an authentic
Pakistani restaurant
in a shopping center.
I traveled to Pakistan
and I lived there for two years,
and this is just like
what I used to eat there.
In the world
of Pakistani food,
this is 100% legit.
101% legit.
101% legit?
[ Laughs ]
So is Farah Khalid,
who grew up in the Punjab region
of Pakistan.
And after traveling the world
with her husband,
they settled in Tempe...
Tandoori chicken tikka ready.
FIERI: ...where she's been
pushing the culinary envelope
since 2002.
Food, all across the board,
is fantastic here.
They cook it in
a traditional tandoori oven,
which is really unique.
FIERI:
It's a blazing-hot clay oven,
cranking out this Indian
and Pakistani classic.
Tandoori chicken tikka.
Rich and spicy,
but not hot.
FIERI: And flavored with
a righteous spice mix
called garam masala.
Holy nutmeg, Batman.
All of these
are going in there?
Yes.
All right,
so let's get it going.
Green cardamom,
whole nutmeg.
All the nutmeg?
Black pepper, cloves,
white cumin seeds.
What is this?
Dried apricot.
It looks like
dried apricot.
This is the whole mace.
It's very strong.
[ Gasping ]
Yeah, you're telling me.
[ Laughs ]
[ Coughs ]
Whoo!
Thanks for the warning
on that one!
Black cardamom,
bay leafs.
The nutmeg pieces are that big
and nutmeg is so hard,
I bet you she goes through
about one of these every week.
Okay, so, now we have
the garam masala.
Okay, and now we are going to
do the chicken tikka.
Ginger garlic.
Pureed ginger
and pureed garlic.
Yes.
The lemon juice.
Oil.
Add food color.
Really?
Number five?
I don't like the tandoori red --
very, very red.
No, I don't like it
that much.
Tomato puree.
The salt.
Chili powder.
Cayenne powder.
And last we are using
garam masala.
[ Laughs ]
You can smell it.
Oh, no.
I know that joke.
That's super potent.
Be careful.
[ Laughter ]
Is it good?
I didn't taste it yet.
You taste it.
That's ready to go.
Oh, that's not
"Be careful."
That's
"You're gonna love it."
The chicken leg
is the best.
You got to go
with that dark meat.
Yeah.
It's a little score so the sauce
will get down in there,
and also it helps
create the crust.
And we're going to skewer
that onto this.
Yes.
Okay, so, we get
all the sauce in there.
Let it go
for overnight.
All right, so, now you go in,
around, down --
Skewer it through.
Yes.
How many pieces will you put
on a skewer?
Two pieces
in one order.
Okay, it's going in
the tandoori.
Yes.
So, 15 minutes.
Yeah.
Yeah!
Thank you.
Is that ghee
or is that butter?
It's butter.
This is the cilantro.
And now you are
going to taste it.
[ Laughs ]
It's good?
This is out of bounds.
[ Laughs ]
Super rich flavor --
a little bit of spice,
little bit of ginger,
a little bit of garlic,
roasted down to where
it's just starting to separate,
come off the bone,
and smoking hot, that is.
Wow!
That is some of
the best chicken
we've ever had
on "Triple D."
I am not kidding you.
Ohh!
WOMAN: It's really tender,
a little spicy.
Tastes amazing.
We had them cater
his second birthday party.
Some Pakistani food
for my kid's second birthday.
We'll do a whole-hog barbecue
for your 5th.
FIERI: Or a whole goat,
like the Pakistanis do.
In Pakistan, goat is
a very common food.
Goat karahi.
All right, so,
what are we making?
We are making
the goat karahi.
I'm going to boil
that goat
in ginger garlic, salt,
bay leafs,
black pepper,
and a little bit of cloves.
And then water.
Cook it down
for how long?
It takes, like,
30 minutes.
What does
"karahi" mean?
"Karahi" means
"the wok."
Do you use a wok a lot
in Pakistani cooking?
Yes.
The ginger garlic.
Ginger garlic mix.
What is this
magnificent mixture?
This is
an onion-based puree.
So, I'm going to put
a little bit of that.
Plus the tomatoes
inside.
And I'm going to
cover it.
And how long
does that go?
This goes, like,
10 minutes.
It becomes more, you know,
tender and more juicy.
So, it really
cooks down.
And now we are going to do
the naan for you.
N-a-a-n?
N-a-a-n.
Let's start
with yogurt.
Milk, dry yeast...
baking powder...
sugar, oil...
eggs...
salt, flour.
So, we are going to make
one garlic and one cheese.
This is the garlic naan.
This is going to be
a cheese naan.
Okay.
We call that
a quesadilla.
And that's it,
right on the side?
You want to try that?
Yeah!
I'm down with it.
Okay.
Right up here?
Oh!
Too high?
No, I think
it's okay.
Okay.
Look at thing puffing.
And now you are
going to do it.
Aah!
Excellent job!
Huh?
What do you think?
Let's see
our goat karahi.
Now I'm going to put
the yogurt in it.
Ground cumin, coriander,
black pepper...
little bit of salt,
sliced ginger...
green chilies,
fresh cilantro.
The most important part --
the butter.
And then we will put a little
bit more cilantro on the top
and a little bit
more ginger.
All right, so,
we've got the garlic naan
and the cheese naan.
There's the one
with the cheese.
That's the cheese.
Mmm!
Now, are you supposed to
eat this by hand?
No, you can use a fork.
Now you tell me.
Oh, my gosh!
The goat cooked down
like that --
It's super tender.
A little bit of the spiciness
to the creaminess.
Reduction of the sauce,
the fresh cilantro in there --
all those little nuances
come together.
Oh, I can't stop!
All-around delicious dish.
It's spicy and always fresh.
MAN:
There's many different options
for ethnic food down here,
but this is the one
that I keep coming back to.
This is a flavor temple.
If you live in Arizona,
anywhere close to Phoenix,
you haven't checked this
place out, you are missing it.
Awesome.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
Look at that!
...we're headed
to Denver, Colorado...
Just a couple of blocks away
from the Colorado State Capitol.
...where a throwback bar...
Oh!
...is turning short ribs
into a big-time burger.
That burger
was nuts!
I'm here in Denver, Colorado,
just a couple of blocks away
from the Colorado State Capitol,
to check out a joint
that's serving up
some righteous bar food
to locals and legislators alike.
This is Prohibition.
It's not too fancy,
but it's not too pub-like.
You can drink good drinks,
eat good food.
I've always had a dream
of owning a bar --
a bar with great food.
FIERI: Well, Jimmy Callahan
can scratch that off the list,
'cause in 2011,
he opened this joint
with longtime buddy and chef,
Toby Prout.
You know, we're kind of,
you know, upscale bar food.
Not just wings
and cheese sticks.
No.
You don't expect this type
of food from any kind of a bar.
Kitchen sink up.
Everything I've had is
just mouthwatering.
MAN: Personally, I like
the Prohibition burger.
Who puts apple
on a burger?
I got the short rib burger.
Oh, my God.
Fantastic.
So, what are we
gonna make?
We're gonna do our
balsamic braised
short rib burger.
We start, obviously, with
salt and pepper -- the basics.
Now we got our hot pan.
Gonna oil it up here.
That is
a screaming-hot pan.
We like a nice, hard sear
on them.
These are gonna be braised
for 12 hours,
you want to lock in
all those juices and whatnot.
We seared them up good.
Now we're gonna do
our mirepoix veg.
Carrots, onions, celery --
The classics.
Then we're gonna go with
our tomato paste.
Hit it with
my balsamic vinegar,
a little bit of red wine
in there.
Peppercorns...
Bay leaf. Garlic.
Just gonna let that wine
reduce just a bit.
We're gonna hit it
with our chicken broth,
which will be
our braising liquid.
Fresh thyme.
We're gonna bring this
up to a simmer
and then put it right over
the boneless short ribs.
Wrap them in foil, pop them
in the oven -- How long?
We do 12 hours
at 200 degrees.
Whoa!
Slow and low.
It's gonna be butter,
baby.
I'm gonna go ahead
and take one for a service.
Get a little bit of the sauce
in the pan.
And then let that reduce
and that's the service sauce?
Yeah.
Nice.
Now we'll cut our meat
for portion,
put it in half again.
That's all going
on one?
Nice full meal
for you.
Into the braising liquid
that's reduced.
Into the braising liquid.
And that is ready
for plating.
Toasted brioche bun.
We have our short ribs.
Just gonna go right down
on the bun.
Just a little bit
of this
beautiful braising liquid
over the top.
Make it nice and juicy --
messy for you.
I want to see
this thing.
Look at that!
It just cut through
like butter.
Wow. It is rich.
It's got
real texture to it.
It's so nice to have
the crunch of the onion,
sweet of that tomato and
the lettuce all coming through.
But that braising liquid
reduced?
Oh!
You delivered.
Thank you.
Well done.
Appreciate it.
Mmm!
Short rib burger up.
That burger
was nuts.
Oh, man, this burger,
you can't get anywhere else.
It's tender as can be.
The sauce is amazing.
It's one of the go-to joints
in Denver?
I believe so, yeah.
There you go.
My twin.
I need you to fill in
on that Saturday shift.
[ Laughs ]
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry -- we got
plenty more joints to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If that was an '80s rock star,
that'd be Naan Jovi.
[ Laughs ]
Naan Jovi!