I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
O-M-G.
...I'm taking
a killer food vacation
in sunny San Diego.
Well, that's a great start.
Now what are we making?
There's the Ocean Beach
burger shack
where my brother
from another mother...
This is gonna be
stupid delicious.
...is raising the bar
on big-time burgers.
Call your mommy!
That's a lot of pastrami!
[ Laughs ]
And just down the street,
a noodle house...
Unbelievable.
...making making phat pho...
Phoggedaboutit.
...way-out wings...
I'll be Jumping Bullet.
Okay.
You be...
Habañero.
...Hoppin' Arrow.
...and a certified fried rice.
KYLE: Can you feel the heat?
I can feel
the heat.
And I can't leave without
a pit stop in North Park...
Whoa!
Look at that move.
...for a slice
from a "Triple D" legend.
They're gonna throw me
out of Italy.
They're gonna throw you
out of Italy?
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
I'm here in San Diego,
or "San Diago"
as Ron Burgundy would call it,
and I'm in Ocean Beach.
I come down here
for a lot of reasons.
But I got to be honest,
the main reason is to see
my brother from another mother.
That's right --
the burger bad boy,
the dude that's got
a tattoo of me on his leg.
Yeah, Mike Hardin.
We're here for a revisit
and update at Hodad's.
Un hamburguesa.
The best hamburger in America.
FIERI: Not much has changed
since we first visited the
original Hodad's back in 2007.
Lean over
and trough it.
You got a couple more
license plates...
It just gets more and more
out of bounds.
...a longer line...
Go ahead and show them
the weirdness.
...and there's that tattoo
I told you about.
Hoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh, there's one other thing.
I have something
called a Guido burger.
You've been asking me
for a couple years
to make pastrami burger.
So, you made it?
Yeah.
MAN: Here comes a Guido.
You guys want try
a Guido burger?
Let's go do
a Guido burger.
Let's rock 'n' roll.
So, what we do is we start off
by putting the bun on.
No butter, no nada?
No. It doesn't need it.
Okay. Okay.
But it does need --
It needs a little spice.
Okay.
So you put a little spice
on the bun,
and that
just kind of helps.
Oh, look at that.
That's what you want --
a little crust to it.
Now, do you mind if I throw
the hamburger patty on?
Go right ahead.
That's a 1/3 pound.
Always like to put a little
spice on top of there, too.
It's a season salt.
Put some scores on there to kind
of flatten it out a little bit.
I'm gonna put
pastrami on.
You're gonna think,
"Oh, no, he's not gonna put
"this much pastrami on.
Oh, no, wait.
How much is he putting on?"
Call your mommy!
That's a lot of pastrami!
[ Laughs ]
I do like the crust.
Little bit of spice --
little bit.
Now what we're gonna do,
on the bottom bun,
we're gonna put
ketchup on it.
Now, this is really
the clincher.
It's the kosher
dill pickle chips.
These are amazing.
You're gonna love this.
Now, you always go
counter-clockwise, always.
It changes the flavor.
You go the other way,
and it's not kosher anymore.
You don't want that.
Now, the Swiss cheese --
A lot of people don't like Swiss
'cause it has holes in it.
I say, "Well,
just eat around it."
You know, you don't
really have to eat --
So, you put this on here.
Okay.
Now, I want the cheese
to kind of melt a little bit.
Good call.
Now, I am gonna put the pastrami
on top of there
'cause that's actually
gonna help.
Now, we're not done.
We're gonna put some grilled,
caramelized onions
on top of that.
Oh, here we go.
Ridiculous.
Isn't that silly?
That's crazy.
Now, crème de la crème,
whatever that means.
We use a brown mustard.
Put plenty of mustard on there.
Look at that.
Now, I'm gonna put this
on top.
This is gonna be
stupid delicious.
I like that.
I'm gonna bring it over.
Oh, my gosh.
Look at that.
Now, this is
the burger diaper.
We're gonna surround
this thing.
Look at that.
[ Laughs ]
And that's the Guido?
That's it.
Do I have anything
right here?
No, no, no, no.
I need, like, a shampoo.
[ Laughter ]
Delicious burger,
but look at this pastrami.
Real deal.
I like how you crisp it up
on the flattop,
and the Swiss cheese.
You give
such a great product.
The burger's righteous.
Such
an eclectic experience.
When somebody names a burger
of this magnitude after you,
you can't say anything
but...
I love you, man.
You're the bomb.
Thanks, brother.
All right.
We got a Guido!
The pastrami
just makes this burger.
It just melts in your mouth.
The flavor's amazing.
So, you got
a "Triple D" joint for me?
There's a place
in Ocean Beach
that's called
the OB Noodle House.
You eat there?
Oh, yeah!
Heck yeah!
They accept you?
Yeah.
I'll make it in?
And the food's legit?
Yeah!
All right.
Hanging out with Mike Hardin
at Hodad's in O.B.
And when we come back,
we're hitting the...
Ocean Beach Noodle House.
See you in a bit.
Yee-hoo!
Let's go.
All right, Hodad.
This is the joint.
How's the food?
Food's amazing,
and the story is even better.
That's
my kind of joint.
This is
the OB Noodle House.
Spicy garlic wings.
Table two ready.
Take it out.
I love the noodle house.
STEVE: Chicken and lettuce wrap
is done.
This is the best restaurant
in Ocean Beach.
FIERI:
A little corner of San Diego
built on sun, sand, and surf.
Ocean Beach
is one of the last remaining
old-school beach communities
in California.
I want to introduce you
to Steve...
'Sup, brother?
...the owner
of the Noodle House.
Oh, you're
gonna love it.
Mike should know.
He's been lining up since '08,
when Steve and Kyle Yeng
first opened the doors.
The brothers are awesome.
They work well together.
FIERI: Taking up
the Chinese culinary path
their parents laid down
when they came to the U.S.
in the '90s.
House special fried rice.
Sizzling fish?
Sizzling fish.
Outstanding.
It's really hard to beat
a big bowl of pho
after a mid-morning
surf session.
Phoggedaboutit.
It would be pho --
P-H-O.
And everybody mispronounces it,
but it's really pronounced...
BOTH: "Fa."
This is what goes
into your pho?
Oh, I got to see this.
All right, so, start it off.
First thing up.
Loading up the bones.
Uh-huh.
Load up the bones.
There's probably about
15 gallons of water.
Uh-huh.
Now we go
with oxtails.
Oxtails.
Next, we got briskets.
60, 70 pounds.
Ton of meat.
Yeah, it's a ton of meat.
Then what
do we got here?
And here, it's called
drop flank.
Flank.
This is
a very, very tough meat.
Where does it
come from?
The cow's chin.
And the last thing
that goes out is the tendons.
Beef tendons.
Uh-huh.
I mean, I know
that we don't use the bones,
so when the meat starts to cook
and it gets done,
we'll pull that?
We'll pull that out.
About five hours or so.
So it doesn't overcook
too much.
Wow. What a process.
Every day?
BOTH: Every day.
So, we got to flavor
the meat, also.
This is rock sugar,
rock candies.
And salt?
And salt.
We actually don't dump
all of it out,
only about half of it.
This one is shallots
that we have peeled and grilled.
This is ginger that we peeled
and also grilled.
The cinnamon's are big.
You can throw it
in the soup, also.
Those you can dig out.
You can find those.
We let this go for about
another 45 minutes or so.
And the last step,
we actually make a spice basket.
Toasted star anise.
A lot of cloves.
Lots of cloves.
Here we got
fennel seeds.
That's all been toasted.
Got it.
Uh-huh. And then we close
the baskets here.
Take the basket of fun,
we drop that in.
15, 20 minutes.
And at the same time,
you can also add fish sauce.
Bring it to a boil.
Add the rest of that --
salt and the sugar.
Yes.
All this work and effort
makes 20 gallons worth of broth?
Of concentrated broth.
Wow.
What a process.
So, this is the brisket
that cooked in there,
the flank
the tendon
that cooked in there.
Rare steak and tripe.
So, we grab
fresh rice noodles.
This is
hot boiling water.
Pretty much just cook it
for maybe about
five, six seconds.
Okay.
That's it?
That's it.
Next, we get the noodle here
and put some brisket...
then some flank...
and these are some tendons.
Put some onions,
tripes on the side...
some green onions...
couple of layers
of rare meat in here.
This is how much meat
you put in this bowl?
That's why we call it
a number-one special.
Now we put some broth.
Then a little cilantros.
Just like that.
It's done.
I just want to try
this broth by itself.
Unbelievable.
Look how clear it is.
Like consommé.
Mmm.
And to kick it up, you can
actually add the sauté sauce --
give it
a little extra flavor.
Get a little bit of spice
in there.
Sauté.
You're gonna have a pretty tough
time finding it this good.
You got a new brother
at OB Noodle House, man.
Number one --
OB special pho.
I've had a lot of pho.
This really is of the best.
Don't you agree?
This is excellent.
Ocean Beach is a really small
beach community.
They're very proud
of their identity.
This restaurant
definitely fits it.
40-plus taps
of really good beer.
FIERI:
And what goes with beer?
Of course, wings.
Spicy garlic wings.
MAN: The absolute best wings
that I've ever had.
Okay, so, what are we
gonna make first?
We're gonna make
the sauté sauces
that we use
for our garlic wings.
Start by just turning up
the fire.
Whoa!
It's pretty hot.
Can't wear a little hair-care
product and be around that.
Okay.
So, hot oil.
STEVE: Hot oil.
Brown ginger,
into the hot oil.
Garlic.
There we go.
Ground lemongrass.
Nice.
And then we got
the ground onions.
And then we stir this
for about 40 minutes.
Who stands here for 40 minutes
and stirs this?
So, now
it's sautéed down.
Got our own chili paste
right here.
Okay.
Chili flake.
Adding some heat right now.
Seriously.
You got the habañero.
"Hoppin' arrow."
Habañero.
I'll be Jumping Bullet.
Okay.
You be...
Habañero.
Hoppin' Arrow.
So, what are you
gonna put in?
All of it.
[ Whistles ]
Then we're bringing
some more heat.
So hot.
Thai chili pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Next up?
Peanut butter.
Good old peanut butter.
Hoisin sauce.
Just give it a sweetness to it.
And a little color.
And then I'm gonna stir it.
How long
is this gonna cook down?
Let it cook for an hour
until the oils start boiling,
and then let it simmer and get
all the flavor for a day or so.
This stays in there
for a day?
Yep.
What are we
gonna make next?
Wings. You got to look
at these suckers.
We prefer to use
the mid-thighs.
We got some garlic, salt,
pepper, sugar.
Make sure we get
all the wings in there.
Now we add the chili-oil sauté
we just made.
Okay. So, let them marinate
for a day...
Yes, sir.
...and drop them
in the fryer.
What temperature
are we gonna cook at?
350.
All right.
So, the wings are done.
Now we put on the wok.
My brother Kyle,
the wok master.
Okay.
So, hot oil.
Garlic.
We're gonna put
some pepper.
Ready?
Uh-huh.
Some wings.
On top of that,
put a little seasoning.
Sugar, granulated garlic,
and white pepper.
And this one,
some green onions.
And that's it.
So, a nice little crisp.
Quick, little sauté.
[ Whistles ]
Gonna be a little spicy,
but let me know how you like it.
Get some ranch.
Garnish it
with some cilantros.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
A little bit of heat,
not too much.
Good amount of spice to it,
little bit of sweet,
just a little bit
of the crispiness on the skin.
They're tender.
They're juicy.
There's a lot of flavor,
a lot of depth of flavor.
I'm impressed.
Tell me that wing
is not the bomb.
Oh, man.
That is excellent.
Not too spicy
on the outside,
but just the right amount
of heat.
Really, really good wing.
What's up next?
House special fried rice.
FIERI: Rocked out with
their dad's signature sausage
when we come back.
O-M-G in O.B.
FIERI:
"Triple D" is in the Ocean Beach
neighborhood of San Diego,
digging in
to the OB Noodle House,
a dream locale
for Steve and Kyle Yeng,
Chinese immigrants
with one heck of a back story.
My grandparents and my parents
both are Chinese.
They immigrated
down to Cambodia
to escape the communists,
the war, and all that.
And life was good
for a while
until they got caught in the
whole Khmer Rouge genocide.
Which sent them to Thailand,
where their dad, Yaoshir Yeng,
used his signature
sausage recipe
to move the family to Cali.
Your dad really changed your
life, his life, everyone's life
by making sausage.
Mm-hmm.
And the savory links
have always had a home
in mom's family recipe.
House special fried rice.
Table three.
So, what do we have here?
Hand-diced pork butts.
Seriously?
Yeah, we actually do it
by hand,
so that way there's
a little more texture to it.
We have a combination
of salt and sugar and soy sauce.
And what in the world
is this?
This is the secret recipe.
I see star anise.
Tremendous amount
of star anise.
Clove.
Okay,
there's cinnamon.
Uh-huh.
Anything else?
Sake.
Sake? Really?
Yeah, sake.
It's been sitting here
for at least a year.
You got to wait like a year
to a year and a half to use it.
Crazy.
Different ingredients, and you
don't add too much of it.
It's pretty strong.
And pretty much like that.
So, you mix this up.
You mix them up.
Put the casing onto
a little sausage stuffer there.
You have
natural casings there.
Let's turn on
the machine.
There you go.
All right.
And you start
to pinch it off now.
Once you go ahead and make the
sausage, you're gonna tie it.
Take the wraps,
wrap it around?
Mm-hmm.
And we just kind of poke
some holes in them
through this casing.
That'll let
some of the air out.
How do you preserve it?
By putting it in the oven --
160 degrees.
Probably like a day or so,
just to get the moisture out.
I have to just try this sausage
'cause it's sitting here.
O-M-G in O.B.
It's got a richness,
a little bit on the sweet side,
and awesome texture
on the outside of it, chewiness.
Well, that's a great start.
Now what are we making?
Right now we're doing
a house special fried rice.
Okay.
Fresh jasmine rice.
And here's the seasoning
for rice.
You know, there's some salt,
some pepper, some garlic,
and put a little sauté sauce
that we just made earlier,
chopped sausage,
and here we also have
jumbo shrimps
and some beef strip loins
that we fried up.
Is there any marinade
on this meat or anything?
A little salt, sugar.
Here's some Chinese broccoli
that we have to blanch in water
really, really fast.
Put a little oil.
We have these eggs
right here.
It looks red because we actually
mix it with Sriracha.
Chopped onions.
Now we put the rice in.
Just constantly shaking it.
Make sure it doesn't burn.
Can you feel the heat?
I can feel
the heat.
So, after it dries out
a little bit,
add the Chinese broccoli
that we blanched earlier.
Put some green onion
into it.
Put a little swirl
of our sesame oil
and just a dash
of soy sauce.
That's it?
That's it.
Dude,
that is smoking hot.
Yeah.
Cilantro.
There you go.
Mmm.
All the rice
is separated.
You do get a little bit
of the heat from the Sriracha.
Mm-hmm.
The sauté, also.
The sauté.
But honestly,
the sweetness of the sausage
just kind of marries
it all together.
Mmm.
All right.
All right, you guys.
I've got an order of house
special fried rice for you.
Every bite is full of flavor,
and you really can't get
the taste anywhere else.
The best fried rice
I've ever had, honestly.
I come here once a week
because the food's so great.
Really a pleasure.
You guys are the best.
Hey, group hug.
We're doing a team hug.
Very nice, guys.
Yeah!
Oh!
The OB Noodle House rocked.
So, listen, I still got
a little time left in the show.
What do you say
when we come back,
we go for a little blast
from the past here in San Diego?
I feel like some Italian.
See you in a bit.
So, here I am in the final leg
of my San Diego tour,
and like I said,
I'm feeling like some Italian,
but not just any Italian,
some really killer
thin-crust pizza.
So, there's only one place
for me to go,
and that's to visit
the newest location
of the "Triple D" favorite --
This is Pizzeria Luigi.
It's my favorite pizza
in town.
Seriously?
Seriously.
WOMAN: It's fresh-baked.
The crust is amazing.
There's a lot of love into it.
It's really good.
FIERI:
And since our visit in '08...
Oh, you gonna go round?
Little dance?
..."Triple D" fans have given
Luigi Agostini so much love
that he opened a second joint
in an area called North Park,
expanding the menu
to 25 totally unique pies.
You tell your friends
back in Italy
this is what kind of
pizza you're making,
what are they gonna say?
They're gonna throw me
out of Italy.
They're gonna throw you
out of Italy?
Until they try them.
'Cause who's gonna deny
a white, veggie pie
called "The Fresh Prince,"
a baked-potato style
called "The Sports Bar"...
This is
one of my favorites.
...or a marinara meatball pie
called "The Crime Scene"?
But I'm here today
to get my Italian brother Luigi
out of his comfort zone.
So, every time
Luigi and I get together,
we make some kind of
unique pizza.
I want to think about what
we can do for a pizza here,
so let's take a little gander
at some of your ingredients.
Sounds cool.
FIERI: I'm in the spicy mood
right now.
Got any hot sauce
around here?
Well,
I got some wing sauce.
This is the wing sauce?
Yes.
Whoa!
Look at that move.
Now, I like,
here at Pizzeria Luigi
how they take everything,
and it's in a nice big format,
but I want to chop this up.
I want this
all to work together.
So, pepperoni,
some sausage.
We'll grab some red onion,
some jalapeño.
Are you done chopping,
or what?
Get it on.
All right. Sweet.
Okay.
Meatball
on top of that, too?
There's meatball
on there, also.
Got to do some garlic.
Ready to go?
Let's get her in.
Oh, hang on.
Hang on.
It needs
some red chili flake.
We don't need
no stinking lid.
[ Laughs ]
What do you think?
Beautiful.
I think we're gonna kill
somebody with this thing.
It's gonna be hot.
Bye-bye.
Bye. See you.
FIERI:
Got to come up with a name.
What about something --
Something like "hot."
Diablo.
I say "El Diablo."
Look at that.
Huh?
That looks good, man.
Now, we have to appropriately
garnish it.
A little bit of Sriracha.
A little wing sauce.
Anybody wants to die?
Where's the cutter?
Oh, boy.
It's got a lot flavor.
Nice little vinegar
coming from the wing sauce.
Mmm.
Chopped up meat's
nice on top of it.
But I think the Sriracha
and the wing sauce,
the jalapeños,
all that coming together
gives it a little bit
of a sting.
Mmm.
I love the spice.
It's starting to kick in
right now.
[ Laughs ]
He's starting to sweat.
Look at that. Right there.
El Diablo.
Nice job.
I like it.
Come on down to Pizzeria Luigi's
second location.
You can get this.
We won't tell
the first location about this.
No, no.
Just keep it a secret.
Nice job, buddy.
Same to you, man.
Damn good -- oh,
it's super kicky, I love it.
That is when your pizza
is done right.
The pizza love that's coming,
pouring off that.
It's kind of like --
It's the mark
of excellence.
Yes, it is.
It is the mark
of excellence.
In the world
of pizza authorities,
this guy
sits on the board.
He's the man.
Good job, brother.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Uh, hello.
Just so you know, I'm trying
to do an interview over here.
But how about you come on back
and have a seat?
Yeah, you want to --
Okay, great.
Well, it's really been
a pleasure.
See you later.
Adiós.
BOY: A bug!
FIERI: Oh, a bug! [ Laughs ]