Hey, there!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Drum roll, please.
...we're getting
a very authentic taste...
Be brave.
...of some
timeless traditions...
All right.
Here comes the big deal.
...in Denver, Colorado...
Come on over here.
...the soul-food spot...
I had food like this
prepared by my mother.
...going real deal
on the rabbit...
Every time you take a bite,
it's more fun.
Have fun.
...and the entrails...
Wow! I bet that's
an acquired taste!
It is!
...in Scottsdale, Arizona...
Your kung fu...
is better than mine.
...the family-run
Italian joint...
Mmm.
...serving up
fresher-than-fresh sausages...
It's a recipe
that's almost 100 years old.
...right next
to a colossal calzone.
Roman Centurion calzone.
Then in Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania...
Looks fantastic.
...a Jamaican vacation...
Just makes me happy
to be here.
FIERI: ...right in the heart
of the city.
How about you
eat one first?
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here in Denver, Colorado.
It seems every time I cruise
into town, I find killer food!
Let's see.
I've had Native American,
East Coast deli.
I mean, I've been to a joint
that was all about sauerkraut!
So, it's no surprise to me
that when I'm here
on Colorado Boulevard
in the Park Hill neighborhood,
that I'd find some real-deal,
Southern soul food!
This is Cora Faye's Cafe.
Ox tails, black-eyed peas,
cornbread.
I had food like this
prepared by my mother.
One piece of catfish.
WOMAN:
Growing up in the South,
this is something familiar
for me.
The catfish, the chicken,
the frog legs,
it all feels like home.
It feels like how I was raised.
FIERI:
To some, it's farm cooking.
Others call it soul food.
But for owner Priscilla Smith,
it's a family thing...
It's authentic Southern cooking
and goes back
many, many generations.
FIERI: ...'cause a lot
of what they ate growing up
came from what was available.
SMITH:
Smothered rabbit.
Now, is this a recipe from home,
from back in Alabama?
Yes, it was handed down
by my mom, Cora.
That rabbit
is just spectacular.
All right.
So, let's get into the rabbit.
Here's the rabbit here.
How do you explain rabbit
to folks?
It's better than chicken.
It's a very lean meat.
It is very lean,
right.
Very tasty.
Okay. So, the rabbit
comes in cleaned.
Yes.
And so I cut it up.
Salt and pepper.
Flour.
Okay.
Oil's heating up.
Now?
Now we're gonna fry
this rabbit
the old-fashioned way.
That's the way to do it.
Iron-cast skillet.
Now, what's your favorite part
of the rabbit?
I think the wing.
The rabbit wings?
Good. 'Cause that's
what I call them, also.
You actually call them
the wings?
[ Laughing ] Yes.
I love it.
I'm just gonna brown
on each side.
We're gonna take
the rabbit out.
Okay.
And then I'm gonna make
the roux -- the gravy.
Then I'm gonna put
the rabbit back in
and let the rabbit
finish cooking.
This is
the chicken bouillon.
Okay. So, we're essentially
adding a little chicken stock.
I don't have
any rabbit stock.
No, if you do,
let me know where you get it.
Okay.
Flour.
Pepper, salt.
Gonna get some water?
Yep.
Mix it up a little bit.
Now we'll we're gonna
just plop the rabbit back in?
Yep.
So, we're gonna let this
cook down how much longer?
Uh, 45 minutes.
It's just gonna sit there
and simmer in the gravy?
Yes.
Rabbit's ready?
I'm gonna plate it.
Okay.
I'm gonna put the rice
in the center.
Oh.
I love greens.
Don't be shy on those.
Tell me about those yams.
These are made
the old-fashioned way.
I boil these.
I don't bake these.
Well,
I'm missing a hush puppy.
Oh, the hush puppy
jumped in my mouth.
[ Laughs ]
All right, rabbit.
Which piece do you like?
Any?
I'll take
whatever you give me.
Oh, here's
a nice piece.
Ooh.
Ohh.
Look at that tenderness.
Let's do
a little rabbit dance.
[ Laughs ]
Wow.
The gravy's
really nice to it.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
This is traditional
Southern cooking.
These recipes go back
over a century in my family.
You're awesome
for sharing it.
Well, thank you.
It is a different flavor
that is just so wonderful.
MAN: It's extremely tender
and extremely tasty.
You feel at home
when you're here.
It does.
It feels like home.
WOMAN: The parlor
with mix-matched furniture.
It kind of reminds me of being
in my grandmother's house.
FIERI:
The menu's also loaded with
Priscilla's family history...
WOMAN:
You have the chit'lings.
FIERI:
...including one old-school dish
I have never in my time
on "Triple D" dared to try.
If you opened up the dictionary
to chit'lings,
that would be the picture?
This would be the picture.
So, this is the intestines
of the pig?
Yes,
the large intestine.
The large intes--
Whoo-hoo!
You smell the aroma?
[ Winces ]
Come on over here so you can see
what I'm doing.
I have to separate the little
silky, mucus part
from the chit'ling parts.
This is cleaning
all kinds of good stuff out.
Is this
a big favorite here?
Yes.
We sell out every Saturday.
Now, do we wash these?
We're gonna wash 'em
really good.
Then we're gonna put 'em
in this pot over here.
Uh-huh.
And we're gonna serve them
with...
With juice --
the gravy.
With juice?
Don't say -- do not say
"pig plumbing" and "the juice."
[ Laughs ]
With the sauce.
Now for the spices.
Now we're gonna go with
the magic spice.
The cumin, the granulated
garlic, and onion, some salt,
some other stuff
you're not telling me.
[ Laughs ]
Now, how long's this
magical mixture gonna cook?
Four to six hours.
Am I gonna get any bread
or anything
to try to get this down with?
How about a piece
of hot cornbread?
How about it?!
And you get a couple of sides --
black-eyed peas.
Ooh, I love black-eyed peas.
Cabbage.
Ooh, I love cabbage.
All right.
Here comes the big deal.
Here comes the big deal!
They're a delicacy.
Take a whiff of that.
Take a whiff.
Don't say "whiff."
Don't say "Take a whiff."
Ooh, look at that gravy.
Mmm, yummy.
Dig in, my man.
Do you recommend that I just try
it with my hot sauce first?
Yes.
Thank you.
Wow!
I bet that's
an acquired taste!
It is!
[ Laughs ]
Wow.
Whoo!
It has a little farmyness.
Okay.
Do you know
what I'm speaking of?
Earthy.
Earthy's another good term.
That's a good food word.
Don't let this be
the first thing on your show
that you didn't like.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, no, no, no.
Listen.
Everybody's got to try
chit'lings once.
Just so you know,
ladies and gentlemen,
that right there...
is chit'lings
four times.
You rock.
Thank you, girl.
Thank you for trying them.
Appreciate it.
Wow.
Here are the chit'lings.
We were raised
on chit'lings.
And this is
real-deal chit'ling?
This is real-deal chit'lings.
You're doing it real-deal,
old-school, Southern soul food.
That's why
this feels like your home.
All right.
It's 'cause you treat people
like it's your home.
Yes, it is.
You're a sweetheart.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
That's what they call me --
T-T-T-Two Scoop.
...we're headed
to Scottsdale, Arizona...
This is like therapy
for me.
...for a family-style feast...
You have to bring
your own wheelbarrow?
...of Italian classics.
Now, this is a good one.
You know that salmon migrate,
ducks migrate,
even caribou migrate.
But only on "Triple D,"
and only on "Triple D,"
would you come to learn
that an Italian restaurant/deli
would migrate
from Toronto to Detroit
to three different locations
here in Scottsdale, Arizona!
This is DeFalco's Italian Deli.
Italian beef up.
My favorite place in the world.
I know that I'm gonna get
the best Italian food
that I can find
when I come in here.
MAN: It's so much fun
to come in here.
Anthony is just a great guy.
FIERI:
That would be Anthony DeFalco,
the third generation DeFalco
to run the family biz.
My parents and my grandparents
all started this business
in Arizona together.
The last stop
of an epic road trip
that great-grandpa Nicola
started in Toronto in 1929.
DeFALCO:
We've been open 40 years
in Arizona.
This is our third location.
We have been following them
the whole time.
FIERI:
For a good reason.
It's homemade food.
Spaghetti, meatball,
up in the window!
Pastas are amazing.
The homemade sausage
is out of this world.
The sausage and pepper sandwich,
it's really tasty, really good.
It's a recipe
that's almost 100 years old.
First thing that DeFalco's
really did was make sausage.
We're gonna make our spice mix
for the sausage
with a little bit of salt...
black pepper...
ground fennel.
[ Whistles ]
Yep.
Whole fennel
on top of that.
We add
a little bit of paprika.
Where's the rest
of the Easy-Bake Oven?
Two Scoop.
That's what they call me --
T-T-T-Two Scoop.
Yeah, that's been
around the block.
This is fresh pork butt,
and we grind this all
in-house ourselves.
We try to make sure
we coat all of it.
We'll add some crushed
red pepper to this,
and then a little more paprika,
'cause this is hot sausage.
Now we're gonna add
some chilled water
to help incorporate
the spices.
We're bringing out
the hopper?
Bring out the hopper.
Natural casing?
I flushed these already.
The wetter this is,
the easier this will go on.
All right.
We'll go ahead and twist
this end up a little bit
so it doesn't all shoot
right out of the casing.
You want me to crank?
Yeah, let's do it.
Let's do it.
This is like therapy for me,
very cathartic.
All right.
Here we go.
If they're a little tighter,
it's quicker,
but if I can feel that there's
a little looseness,
I'm gonna spin these
a little bit more
than I typically would.
So, we're all linked up now.
It'll hold itself tight?
Yeah. See that?
Ahh, see, I always was
scared to do that.
And we just go...
Your kung fu...
is better than mine.
Thank you, sir.
I will try.
Just pop 'em
in the convection,
brown 'em on one side,
brown 'em on the other,
they're good to go.
These are the fried peppers
and onions
that go on our sandwich,
sautéed with a little bit
of olive oil and red onion,
garlic, kosher salt,
and some fresh ground
black pepper.
And then at the very end,
we add Marsala wine again
and let that all stew
for a little bit.
And you get
those juices going.
Let's make our sandwich.
We've got a nice
Italian sub roll here.
You have a local bakery
that's --
We do.
He was a baker from back east,
best bread in town.
So, go ahead and put
a couple links on here.
A couple?!
Couple.
And I don't want anybody
leaving here hungry.
That's the rule.
Go ahead and add some sauce,
fresh-made peppers and onions.
Lastly, we're gonna put
the provolone cheese on there
just like that.
We'll put a little bit
more sauce on top.
And then into
the convection oven we go
for about 60 seconds.
I knew
I was gonna have to wait!
All right.
So, once everything's
all baked off,
we're gonna pull this out,
get a nice little toast going.
Here we go,
ladies and gentlemen.
Drum roll, please.
[ Imitates drum roll ]
Mmm.
Look at the moisture
in that sausage.
A little sweetness
from that Marsala.
And then this nice
crunchy bread
with the tomato sauce
that you make yourself
that comes
from a family recipe.
That's a real
sausage and pepper sandwich.
This is what
an Italian deli's all about.
Indeed.
Over the top, man.
Great job.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
MAN:
I love it when you take a bite
and that cheese
just strings along.
So, evidently,
you don't like the sandwich.
Absolutely awful.
[ Laughs ]
Try to take a few breaths
between that.
MAN: They have all of the stuff
that they make here.
You got a good deli counter
where you can get the meats
and the cheeses.
You get imported stuff
from Italy.
MAN: This is real.
This is the one?
Real Italian food.
But I'm gonna use their calzone
as my barometer...
All rise
for the Centurion.
...when we come back.
Ohh.
FIERI:
"Triple D" is hanging out
at DeFalco's
Italian Deli and Grocery...
Meat and cheese lasagna.
FIERI: ...the epitome of what
an East Coast Italian deli
is all about.
There's only one curveball.
We're in Scottsdale, Arizona.
This little gem in the desert.
WOMAN:
Centurion calzone.
The calzone is wonderful.
You can't eat the whole thing,
but you can have it
for lunch tomorrow.
We're now gonna make the...
Roman Centurion calzone.
We're gonna go ahead
and start off with some semolina
here on the table
to stretch our dough.
Get it up on the peel.
So, we're
all stretched out there.
Pecorino Romano mix
with a little bit of spices
and some garlic --
adds a little bit of flavor.
This is
our house-made mozzarella.
We make this daily.
Really?
Dig in.
I'll make you some
if you like.
So tender.
Just enough salt in there
to give it a little taste.
Next we're gonna add
thin-sliced sopressata to this.
Some roasted peppers.
We roast these in-house.
We kind of marinate them
in a little bit of olive oil
and some fresh parsley.
Kalamata olives,
fresh tomato on there.
We add some fresh basil.
Last layer of cheese.
Seal her up.
Little tuck and roll.
Cut the top a little bit.
So it doesn't steam
into a gigantic football.
And what temperature
are we running that oven?
As hot as we can get
a deck oven to go, about 600.
About 10 minutes,
it'll be ready to rock.
Bring it on in.
All right.
All rise
for the Centurion.
Wow!
Yeah, they're hearty.
You have to bring
your own wheelbarrow?
By the time they get done
eating it, you'll need one.
And this also comes with
the sauce that we made earlier.
Got a little juice coming
out of that fresh mozzarella
and those tomatoes in there.
Look at that.
The basil, the sopressata,
the house-made mozzarella.
Oh.
Great dough.
Some real chew to that.
The balance is fantastic,
the crust is great,
the oven temperature's
perfect.
The tomato sauce
is great.
I mean, you'd be
very hard-pressed
if you brought somebody
in here blindfolded
to tell them that they weren't
in a New York deli.
That's a great compliment.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
It's great food, man.
Thank you very much, man.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Real deal.
FIERI:
You like the calzone?
Yeah.
Are we gonna be able
to get through this, you think,
by the time
the show's over?
I don't know.
There we are.
Very nice.
There you go.
It is old-school authentic.
There's nothing like it.
DeFalco's!
Number one, hands down.
Too legit to quit,
right?
FIERI: Coming up...
It's good?
Good.
...we got to head north
to Philadelphia...
It hits the hot spot.
FIERI: ...to get some righteous
grilling from the grill --
Jamaica, that is.
Can't get any more Jamaican
than this.
I'm here
in downtown Philadelphia,
or Center City,
as they call it,
on the West Side, to check out
a real-deal Jamaica joint.
Why is it real deal?
'Cause I hear they're one
of the only places in town
that's cooking
with a charcoal barbecue pit.
This is the Jamaican Jerk Hut.
Can't get any more Jamaican
than this.
WOMAN:
Curry shrimp roti for you.
It's been here for,
God, 25 years.
I'm not sure where else
to get such good food.
Ackee salt fish --
very, very good.
MAN:
You come here for fresh food,
you come here for
a really laid-back vibe,
and you come here for Lisa.
FIERI:
That'd be Miss Lisa Wilson,
who picked up this spot in '07
after running a slightly
different kind of place.
So, you were working
at a Jewish temple...
Yes.
...as a kitchen manager...
...making
what type of food?
Kugel.
Gefilte fish.
[ Chuckles ]
All of your
Jamaican favorites.
[ Laughter ]
And what did you know
about Jamaican food?
Well, my mom's Jamaican, and
I have a Jamaican background.
Okay, so you've eaten
Jamaican food at home.
Every day.
Courtesy of Chef Teddy Hall,
a Montego Bay native
who's definitely keeping it real
in the kitchen.
You cook any other type of food,
or only Jamaican food?
Only Jamaican food.
WILSON: We're the only Jamaican
restaurant with a jerk pit.
So you really get
that charcoal, that wood,
that char to it,
that flavor.
Exactly.
And that's what makes it
real-deal Jamaican.
That's what makes it
real good.
What's your favorite item
on the menu?
Jerk chicken.
Jerk chicken, the classic.
Okay,
jerk chicken platter ready.
I like hot, and I like spicy.
So, we'll start
with the jerk sauce first.
I know what these are.
Scotch bonnet pepper.
Want to have one and taste?
'Cause they're
nice and sweet?
How about you
eat one first?
[ Laughs ]
Okay, get me started.
Tell me what we have.
We have garlic, onion,
scallion.
Lots of ginger.
Not too much.
Thyme.
Very key.
Scotch bonnet pepper.
Any of those
or just Scotch bonnet?
Scotch bonnet.
You'll like these.
Salt...
black pepper...
granulated garlic.
Granulated garlic --
Is that big on the island?
Yeah.
Allspice.
Soy sauce.
That doesn't look like
regular soy sauce.
Mushroom soy sauce.
Oh, there you go.
When this is going,
what do you think about?
Driving.
[ Laughs ]
What kind of car?
Your car.
My car.
We're gonna marinate
the chicken.
So, I pour this jerk sauce
on the chicken.
Then I rub it up.
Okay, so, now we're gonna
wrap this up,
let it marinate
for 24 hours.
Yep.
Put that in the cooler.
It's very hot so its skin
will tear right off.
We need the skin on it.
All right, how long's
the chicken gonna take?
Like 20 minutes
right now.
20 minutes?
Yeah.
So, this is
just to mark it,
get some nice crust
on it.
Yeah.
Before I finish
grilling it on there,
put it in the oven,
finish it up.
How long's it finish
in the oven?
Another 10 minutes
will be good.
Look at that.
Looks fantastic.
Mmm.
You just cut it
into little chunks?
Yeah.
Oh.
What do we serve it with?
Rice and peas...
cabbage...
and plantain.
What is this?
Jerk sauce.
I will pour the sauce
on the chicken for you.
There you go.
It's good?
Good.
"Excellent."
I don't like "good."
[ Laughs ]
It's excellent.
And this is
just melt-in-your-mouth.
Well, then...
you have
this awesome marinade --
adds a little bit
of sweetness to it,
and then it makes this
almost like a barbecue sauce
that goes over the top.
You reserve marinade.
That's the key
to the end of that.
Nice job.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Chicken is really nice
and spicy.
MAN: Flavor is amazing,
and it just makes
your whole taste buds just pop.
And it's tender, and it's hot.
It hits the hot spot.
When you come for the food,
you want to be like
you're in Jamaica.
You could just feel
the island breeze as you eat.
Sometimes she has
the music playing.
Make you happy.
That's what it seems like.
It's like this is
my happy place.
WILSON:
Very authentic.
FIERI:
It is very authentic.
It has a great feel.
Teddy's amazing.
I think the food's
the best part.
That is the best part.
So, that's it for this trip.
But don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm in the country,
pedaling like Fled Frintstone --
Fled Frint-- Fled Frintstone --
Fled Frinstone.
Fred Flintstone?
[ Chuckles ]