Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Take me
to promised land.
...respect your elders...
My ma said
we couldn't do it.
...especially when they're
passing on the family secrets.
Oh, talk to me.
In Carlsbad, California...
Now we're
cooking with gas.
...an Italian-American spot
digging into grandpa's playbook.
This is
the old-school Italian gravies
and meatballs and pasta.
In Troutdale, Oregon...
This is starting to get
a little surreal.
...the outdoor patio paradise...
Yee-ha! Peow!
...run by a rock star dishing
out her mama's favorites.
My mom came from the old school
and did it all.
And in San Francisco,
California...
That level phenomenal.
...authentic Mexican
cooked up
by the third generation.
Do I have any
on my face?
All over your face.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here
in Troutdale, Oregon,
about 18 miles
from downtown Portland
to check out a joint
here on Highway 30
right along the Sandy River
that opened in the 1940s
feeding loggers and locals.
Well, it turned into
all kinds of restaurants
until it ended up being closed
as a biker bar.
It's been reopened,
refurbished, and renewed
by a local restaurant owner that
I hear is a real firecracker.
This is Shirley's Tippy Canoe.
Hey, diner guy.
You want to race
for some pink slips?
[ Tires squeal ]
MAN: If I would describe Shirley
in one phrase,
it would be high-speed,
low-drag.
Quite the sassy little gal.
FIERI: A sass that 40-year
restaurant vet Shirley Welton
brought to the table when
she picked up this joint in '07.
You might say
it was a biker bar.
It used to get
pretty rough here.
Shirley has done
a wonderful job here.
I think
she's Superwoman.
No, no, no.
Just have a lot of energy.
That's all.
[ Laughs ]
This is starting to get
a little surreal.
But the food
is keeping everything grounded.
Captain's plate.
Everything Shirley does
is homemade and fresh.
Sloppy joe.
MAN: Thank you.
FIERI: Just the way
her mama taught her.
Well, we're gonna
make sloppy joes.
I'm gonna go ahead
and cut it in half.
Where did you learn
to cook?
From my ma.
You're amazing.
What do you do
in your spare time?
Fool around.
[ Laughs ]
I'll be over here.
All right. We're gonna take this
and go grind it up?
Okay, let's do it.
We're gonna
grind it twice.
All right. So, we take this,
and we make sloppy joes?
Yes.
Gunpowder.
We're making gunpowder?
We're making gunpowder,
and that's our spices.
All this
goes to gunpowder?
Salt, paprika.
Then we're gonna go ahead
and put some celery salt in it.
And we're gonna put
nutmeg, curry.
Curry.
Just a little.
Allspice,
ground white pepper.
Thyme.
Thank you.
Thyme after thyme, huh?
Ground bay leaves.
And marjoram?
Coriander.
Cayenne?
Oh, cayenne.
Yeah, we are.
Whoa!
Hey, we got to put
some zip into it.
Granulated garlic.
Got some garlic.
A little clove.
Oh, yeah.
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Lighten it up
with the clove!
Trust me, honey.
Onion powder.
And there we go
with onion powder.
50 points.
Sage.
Cumin.
And the last one...
Ginger!
Yeah.
[ Laugh ]
I've never had more fun
mixing spices.
Snap it down.
Okay. There.
All right.
[ Whistles ]
Gunpowder.
Yee-ha! Peow!
Gonna make
the sloppy joe.
Okay.
Let's brown the meat here.
Next up, white onions.
Green peppers, celery,
some cayenne, some salt.
We're gonna take
some oregano,
chili powder,
and bay leaves.
And then we have
some minced garlic,
some black pepper,
and then we have some cumin.
All that together?
Yep.
Give it a swirl here.
Get after this.
It smells great so far.
Okay.
WELTON: Okay.
Worcestershire sauce,
vinegar.
Lemon-lime soda?
Uh-huh.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Tomato sauce,
tomato soup.
Now, how long
are we gonna let this cook?
Oh, we're gonna simmer it
for probably an hour.
And what are we gonna
serve it with?
We're gonna serve it
with a hamburger patty.
Gunpowder.
WELTON:
Put the sauce on.
Cheese.
And then
we're gonna steam it.
[ Whistles ]
Finish it off
with a green onion.
I noticed that
there's no top for the bun.
It's underneath there.
We don't close ours.
Mm.
Nice little
medium-rare burger.
You get
a lot of burger in this,
and it's not just
a bunch of sloppy joe.
But this is hearty.
It's real food.
That's the real deal.
That's a good burger --
sloppy burger joe.
Sloppy joe burger.
[ Laughs ]
Not like a normal sloppy joe.
The spice on it
that just lingers in your mouth.
It's a little bit sweet, too,
so it's perfect for me.
I love coming here.
FIERI: And getting here --
Well,
that's half the adventure.
MAN: It's a very fun drive.
You sit out here in
the beautiful Douglas fir trees
that are native
to the Pacific Northwest.
Hamburger steak.
It doesn't matter what you have.
It's always good.
Chicken fried steak.
WELTON:
Table 8, Polish dip.
The Polish sausage French dip
is very good.
FIERI: Pork butt.
There you go.
Pork butt.
There we are.
And this we're cutting up
to make the Polish sausage?
Mm-hmm.
My mom came from the old school.
You did it all,
you know?
You cut and grind it
yourself.
Kind of
a course grind there.
Yes, it is.
Put half of
the ingredients in,
then I put
the seasoning in.
The garlic?
The garlic.
A little sage.
Pepper, salt, marjoram.
And then
we put the rest in.
So
it's right in the middle.
All right, here we go.
'Cause
we don't have all day.
[ Shakily ]
I can't hold onto it any longer.
Let's just stop it.
Okay.
Make the patty,
about 7 ounces.
And it has to be
kind of elongated.
We're gonna
put the sausage down.
Put a little butter here.
Put the onions.
Then we put the green pepper,
the brown sugar,
and put it on the onions
to caramelize the onion.
So, we cook both sides.
So, the au jus is ready?
The au jus is ready.
Nice little toast
on that.
Here we are.
[ Whistles ]
Nice patty.
Paul Bunyan, or what?
And then we stab it.
The sausage sandwich
usually is juicy enough.
Why put a dip with it?
Well, you try it
and see what you think.
Good sausage sandwich,
you know?
Peppers and onions,
you can't beat that.
But now dip it.
All right.
Oh, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
That makes it. I mean,
it's good as it is,
not overseasoned,
the nice toasted bread.
Then that bread
soaks up some of that jus.
When you stop by here,
that's kind of
the old-school sandwich
you'd want to have.
It's the best food around.
Just a wonderful,
wonderful place.
FIERI: Just all the components,
sitting in the nostalgic room,
it just has a really cool feel
about it.
Make sure she's here
when you come down.
Coming up...
Yum!
...we're headed
to Carlsbad, California...
I'll take
"tree" [three].
You want
"tree" [three] of them?
...where family traditions...
No out of a mold
with this one.
No. No molds.
...are spearheading
authentic Italian eats.
You almost got it
to the corner.
Almost got it.
How about I just drag
the sheets over the bed, boss?
So, I'm about 35 miles
north of downtown San Diego
in Carlsbad, California.
And of all places,
I'm in a strip mall.
They've got exactly
what you'd expect --
grocery store, pet store, a gym.
I mean,
the usual cast of characters.
And speaking of characters,
I hear you got to check out
a joint where
they're doing old-school,
East-Coast,
Italian-American food.
This is Spirito's Italian Diner.
The food is awesome.
Chicken Parm
with a side of manicot.
WOMAN:
I come from an Italian heritage,
and when I smell
his food cooking,
it takes me back.
FIERI: 'Cause owner Mike Spirito
is dishing up
the Italian he learned
in his family's restaurant
in Elizabeth, New Jersey.
This is
the old-school Italian gravies
and meatballs and pasta.
East-Coast Italian?
East-Coast Italian.
But after a SoCal vacation
in the winter of '78,
he brought his family recipes
to the West Coast,
like Pizza di Politana,
lasagna with meat sauce,
and of course,
the gold standard.
Spaghetti meatballs.
FIERI: Smothered in
the Spirito family marinara.
WOMAN:
They're thick, they're meaty,
and the sauce over it
just combines all the taste.
What are we gonna make?
Our Roman meatballs
with the pignoli and raisins.
Pine nuts and raisins
in this?
Yes.
Take the ground beef,
add the eggs.
Italian parsley,
plain bread crumbs,
not seasoned.
It's a combination
Parmesan/Romano.
Do it before I eat
all those pine nuts, man.
Then we've got a little
black pepper, salted garlic.
Raisins.
And half the amount
of the pine nuts that you need.
Because you finished them.
Because I've been eating them.
So, then we incorporate
all the ingredients here.
And what size balls
are you gonna form?
We do 3.5 ounces.
Okay.
Cook it off in the oven
for about 20 minutes at 400.
We put some
right in the gravy.
Okay,
we're ready to go?
We're ready to go.
All right.
We got a couple of the meatballs
soaking in the sauce.
How many meatballs
you get with an order?
Whatever you want.
Some people like three.
I'll take
"tree" [three].
You want
"tree" [three] of them?
A little Romano.
A little pepper.
That's all she wrote.
That's
old-school Jersey gravy.
Not overdone,
not too spiced.
Good amount of garlic,
though.
I'll tell you that much.
Look at
the size of these things.
That's
a really nice meatball.
Thank you.
I like it with
that little raisin in there,
a little bit
of the sweetness.
Nice job, boss.
All right.
The garlic, the pine nuts,
everything about it is fabulous.
As good as the food is,
we come here just as much
to see Mike and the whole crew.
WOMAN: He likes to talk about
his history in New York
and New Jersey
and all the things
that he's done
and the places he's been,
the places he's cooked.
FIERI: But he lets this
big seller do all the talking.
We've got the raviolis
with the meat gravy.
FIERI:
A dish his grandpa started
serving back in the '20s.
We're making
handmade ravioli.
You really do this by hand
all the time?
Yes.
It's nice, beautiful dough.
Very soft.
Feel it. You feel it?
No, I see it.
It's nice and silky and thin
and not pulling back.
We're gonna work it.
Now we're
cooking with gas.
Yeah.
All right.
Looking good.
You almost got it
to the corner.
About I just drag
the sheets over the bed, boss?
All right.
So, now we're making the filling
for the cheese ravioli?
Yes.
We've got
the New York-style ricotta.
And then we have
Parmesan,
fresh, chopped Italian parsley,
black pepper, the eggs.
We'll mix it
a little bit.
You're gonna do it
with your hands?
I'm gonna do a little bit.
Yeah, you know.
Hey, how, on the first one,
did you already get me with it?
How? Because
your finger was in the way.
There we go.
We got the filling.
Then we take the egg wash.
So everybody sticks.
We're gonna
put the filling.
Whoa!
Yeah, these are
nice-sized raviolis.
And then we'll be
pulling the pasta over
to cover these babies.
Make the pocket there.
Okay.
It's like a doctor doing surgery
right now.
Very rustic.
No out of a mold
with this one.
No. No molds.
We go straight into
salted water.
They just take
about 5 minutes to cook.
Look at
the size of these monsters.
Four to a plate.
Goes beautiful
with the meat gravy.
A little Parmesan,
Pecorino, Romano.
Serve it with
a little homemade foccacia.
And you're ready to go.
All right. Let's look at
one of these monsters.
There's, like,
1/4 cup of the ricotta in there.
Oh, man.
The pasta itself
is super tender,
and the ricotta inside of it
is just creamy as can be.
Mmm.
Good old-school meat sauce
right there, man.
Yum!
When I bite into that,
it's like a pizzazz.
So, here's what's funny
about this place.
You got this little mom-and-pop
joint inside of a strip mall,
but you're doing it
all real deal.
Keeping it real.
Mike,
you're the best, man.
Up next...
This is
everything but boring.
...we're headed north
to San Francisco, California...
Oh, my gosh.
...for a new twist
on old-school Mexican.
That was from one bite.
That ridiculous.
[ Bell dings ]
So, I'm here
in San Francisco, California,
in an area that I have
driven through a million times
on the way to the airport
but never visited.
It's called
the Inner Sunset District.
Now, right across the street,
Golden Gate Park.
Five miles that way,
Ocean Beach.
And I'm here to check out
a Mexican joint
that's doing it real deal.
This is Nopalito.
Something you're not gonna get
at a typical taqueria.
MAN: Everything is homemade,
and that's part of the reason
it's good.
FIERI: Well, that
and the folks behind Nopalito,
Allyson Jossel and Jeff Hanack,
local restaurateurs who dug
their chef, Gonzalo Guzman,
so much,
they made him a partner.
He's always wanted
to cook his cuisine,
and so it was just
a logical choice
to open a restaurant
to honor Mexican cuisine.
FIERI: Together,
they opened this joint in 2012,
with a Mexico-meets-Bay Area
attitude.
Pozoles up.
This pozole's probably one of
the best I've ever had.
And a quesadilla...
Quesadilla Chicharrón
is up.
...loaded with some of
my favorite ingredients.
What are we on to, chef?
Carnitas for our Quesadilla
Roja con Chicharrón.
Chicharrón I know to be
the fried pork skin,
and that's gonna be
added to this, as well?
Yeah.
All right. Let's go.
For the carnita,
we're gonna do our bouquet,
which is just oranges
with some onions.
Garlic.
Real cinnamon.
From Mexico, too.
And then bay leaves.
Manteca, or lard.
If you're gonna do it,
you got to use the lard.
We're gonna cook the pork
in the manteca.
Unrefined Mexican sugar.
The bouquet goes in.
Now,
that is a carnitas paddle, man.
And we're gonna let it go
an hour, hour and a half.
Now what are we making?
We're gonna cook our pork skin
for the chicharróns.
Poach it in hot water
with a little salt.
Once it comes to a boil,
we're just gonna let it sit
for two minutes.
Pull it out.
Cool it down.
Cut it into pieces.
And then we're gonna dehydrate
it in the oven overnight.
Look at this.
It's practically a chip.
I mean,
this thing is as hard --
[ Pork skin cracks ]
That hard.
But that's awesome because
the less moisture that's in it,
the more it's gonna bloom up
when it fries.
Any moment,
they're gonna start.
And you just go boom,
boom, boom.
Look at that --
light and crusty.
[ Crunches ] Oh.
So,
our carnitas in the back...
They're ready.
So, you're just gonna add
the milk and dark beer.
And then we continue to cook
for...
5 to 20 minutes.
Right.
So, we're gonna
pull out a little piece.
Then we're gonna add
some salsa to it.
So, this is ready
for our quesadilla.
Let's make our tortilla.
Masa.
And this is a paste,
or adobo.
Flavored tortilla?
Yes.
Nice and red.
Some nice Jack cheese.
Some carnitas.
And then a little oil
to fry it.
Just to put
a little more crisp on it?
Now open it.
That's when we add
our queso fresco.
The crunchy chicharróns
go right inside.
Right inside.
Fresh cilantro
and fresh onions.
Just close it, and pretty much,
that's ready for you.
Now she's ready to go.
[ Whistles ]
The flavor's outrageous.
Light, crispy tortilla.
The crunch of the chicharrón.
A pork that is super rich.
It's not just
regular carnitas.
And usually, a quesadilla
is most often boring.
This is
everything but boring.
Wow.
Right. That level phenomenal.
Give me two minutes,
should be ready.
Reminds me of
my grandmother's carnitas.
FIERI: Take everything that
you thought was Mexican food
and take it
a step further.
I'm hanging out
with Chef Gonzalo.
And when we come back,
I have to get ready
to experience torta
to a whole nother level.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
FIERI: Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in San Francisco
with Chef Gonzalo
at the Nopalito restaurant.
And I got to tell you something.
The dude is real deal.
The Mexican food is like
you've never seen before.
And now we're
in to making...
Pambazo.
Oh, exactly.
Which is
a Mexican sandwich.
Mexican sandwich?
I assume chorizo
is the foundation.
Chorizo's
one of the ingredients.
All right.
So, get us started, buddy.
Ground pork butt?
Yeah.
Fresh garlic,
coriander, cumin,
pinquito picante,
dried thyme, ginger, cinnamon.
Marjoram?
Cloves, black pepper,
nutmeg, dry oregano.
Pink curing salt.
Regular salt.
Adobo.
And then
apple cider vinegar?
Apple cider vinegar.
Very nice.
Take me
to promised land.
Oh, talk to me.
So, this salsa is the same base
that we use for the pozole.
Okay.
So, we're gonna press
a little bit.
You can see
it's crispy on both sides.
When I open it,
you can see some steam coming,
so it's hot inside.
Crispy on the outside.
Chorizo.
While we wait for that
to get hot,
we're just gonna
build the sandwich.
First, the avocado.
Put some of
this salsa escabeche.
Pico jalapeño,
so pico vegetable.
We've got
Mexican jardiniere.
And these are papas?
All right. Yeah.
Those are potatoes
with the same salsa.
Ohh!
Use some
before you finish them all.
Make sure
it's really hot.
Then we're gonna add
some cabbage,
onions,
mixed with some crema.
Queso fresco on top.
And then on the top side
of the sandwich,
gonna put some crema.
That's your sandwich
right there.
Oh, my gosh.
So, you've got to eat this
with a beach towel.
Do I have any
on my face?
All over your face.
That was from one bite.
That's ridiculous.
This right here is a complex
dish made into a sandwich.
You get
that little jardiniere.
You get that salsa,
a little bit of the vinegar
cutting some of the sweetness
of the potatoes and the queso.
Mmm.
It's not like any torta
I think I've had.
There's a lot of depth.
There's a lot going on.
It's an excellent sandwich.
Nice job.
Thank you.
In the category of Mexican food,
this is wow.
Out of control.
Out of bounds.
This was an experience
and then some.
This guy
is incredibly talented.
In the "wow" factor,
it's way up there.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Hi, diner guy.
You lost fair and square.
Where's the pink slip?
Got it right here.
How do I spell your last name,
Shirley?
Which one?
W-e-l-t-o-n.
Thank you very much.
[ Laughter ]