Hey, everybody,
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're looking for America's
greatest diners, drive-ins,
and dives.
This trip...
You have got to make some sense
of what's going on here.
...it's a pair
of dynamic duos.
Ooh.
In Denver, Colorado...
Maybe it is gonna be
a mile high.
...the triple-threat joint...
That's a first.
...for drinks, pizza...
That's where the manhole cover
from Flavortown comes from.
...and bodacious biscuit.
Holy biscuit mania.
Then in Scottsdale, Arizona...
[ Imitates whirring ]
...a mom-and-pop spot...
This is getting more odd
as we go.
...scratch-making
their rendition
of morning-time classics.
And say "goodnight" to Guy,
'cause he's gonna pass out
in the car.
That's all right here, right now
on "Triple D."
I'm here in the Bluebird
district of Denver, Colorado.
Now, they call it that
because right down there --
that's the Bluebird Theater
that opened in 1913.
Anyhow, here to check out
a place -- let's see --
it started as a bar.
Then they added in
a pizza joint.
a biscuit place.
So, now we've got ourselves
Fat Sully's, Denver Biscuit,
all under the roof
of the Atomic Cowboy.
Order up -- Franklin!
The Denver Biscuit Company
is the place to come to
in Denver for good food.
Order up -- Dahlia.
This is as good as any biscuit
I ever had in Georgia.
Eggs and bacon -- this is
my favorite biscuit.
MAN: Everything just tastes
better in between a biscuit.
FIERI: Like shrimp and grits
and chicken pot pie.
Biscuit-based everything.
This is the good stuff --
plain-out good food.
Yum.
FIERI: And it's a long way
from the dive bar owner
Drew Shader took over in '04.
When we started, we were
a whiskey and PBR bar.
That was it.
But this South Florida native
wanted a taste of home
in the Mile High City,
so he brought in his buddy,
chef Jonathan Larsen.
So you're like
biscuit badasses?
Yeah.
Like this hot mess of
a barbecued pork sandwich.
And the Elmer.
Let's fire up
some biscuits.
All-purpose flour first.
Some cake flour.
We got buttermilk powder.
Buttermilk powder -- really?
Yeah.
Little salt, little sugar,
little baking powder, and then
the secret -- cream of tartar.
Really?
Yeah. It just works.
And we got
to grab the grater.
We have three of these.
This is Darth Grater?
Yeah.
Frozen butter.
I want to push.
Okay, I'll hold.
Look at that.
It's like a butter
cotton candy machine.
Yeah.
So that's it?
For right now.
Now we're gonna add
our buttermilk,
yogurt,
and some whole eggs.
It has to be incorporated
for about a minute.
So we're gonna mix up
the biscuits.
Now we're gonna just add
a little bit...
...more flour.
It's about 2 of these cups.
It kind of varies.
That's it.
Mixture's out of the way.
Now time to roll.
Time to roll.
Look at that.
It's like
a Sleep System pillow.
We cut it in half.
I'm going to just
knead it.
So what have we got going here?
Are we gonna roll it again?
Yeah, we're just gonna get it
kind of into a rectangle.
So we're just gonna
keep rolling out.
You can see that butter
still is right there.
We got to check it
and make sure.
Ooh, yeah.
Not very -- not yet.
It's the right consistency.
Then we punch and cut.
I'll go straight down on them.
Hoh!
That is a monster!
Maybe it is gonna be
a mile high.
[ Chuckles ]
Take a little pan spray.
Now they're gonna go
in a oven --
350 degrees for 18 minutes --
convection oven.
All right.
Off to the oven.
Now pork butt for this
pulled pork Elmer.
We got salt first,
black pepper.
This is all the dry rub that's
going for this pork butt.
Paprika, chili powder,
a little cumin.
Brown sugar?
Oh, yeah.
And some cayenne.
So, generously rub this?
We're gonna chill it
for 24 hours.
We'll wrap it
in plastic wrap.
Get it in the smoker
in how long?
10 hours
we'll smoke it for.
What kind of wood?
Hickory.
Very nice.
And you also make
your own barbecue sauce?
Oh, yeah.
Word.
Okay. Wow!
It's a cornucopia
for barbecue sauce.
Fire it up, man.
Yellow onions,
red and green apples.
That's a first.
Touch of Worcestershire.
Worcestershire --
a lot of it.
ACV?
Apple cider vinegar.
I'm gonna throw --
Pork bones.
...a couple bones
in there.
Yeah, why not?
Brown sugar.
Lemon juice.
Little oil,
little horseradish,
little Colman's Mustard,
garlic,
we'll go a little black pepper,
red chili flakes,
a little bit of cayenne,
ketchup, little honey...
Darling.
...and a little bit
of molasses.
Throw it on a little
medium-low heat.
This should be good.
Holy biscuit mania.
Look at the size
of this thing.
Watch,
I can hide behind it.
Didn't even know I was there,
did you?
Mmm.
Is that flaky goodness
or what?
Wow, that's good.
We're gonna put more in this?
Oh, yeah.
Start with our pulled pork,
throw it in the hot pan,
and we just made
tomato water.
Just something
to rehydrate it with.
We add a little barbecue sauce
that we made.
Then we just
pile on the pork.
Then we do
our house-made pickles,
a little house-made cole slaw,
then the crispy onions.
That's a mound of trouble.
Is everything this big?
Yeah.
That's ridiculous.
How do you eat it?
Fork and knife.
Only way.
Wow.
The biscuit is so tender
and so flaky and light,
then you did a really nice job
on the pork --
the rub, the smoke,
a little tomato water gig...
and the barbecue sauce
is eccentric.
Chef, well done.
The Elmer is a sloppy mound
of phenomenal deliciousness.
It's messy,
but it's good messy.
it's good messy,
okay, I like that.
MAN #2:
You can't beat the biscuits,
and then you can't beat
the pizza in the afternoon.
FIERI: Oh, yeah.
In case you forgot,
this joint also has
a pizza place!
Okay, you have got
to make some sense
of what's going on here.
You got a bar,
a pizza joint,
a biscuit joint,
and you have two food trucks.
Yep. Two food trucks
out of this same building.
I've seen some crazy stuff
across the country.
That might just
take the cake.
It is crazy.
But you really
haven't seen crazy
till you get a load of the pizza
skins these dudes are tossing.
It's like a bed sheet.
We're heading over
to Fat Sully's
for some big-time pie
when we come back.
It's not even
big enough yet.
[ Laughs ]
[ Bicycle bell dings ]
FIERI: Welcome back.
We're here in the Bluebird
District of Denver, Colorado.
I'm hanging out
with big chef John.
We're at
the Atomic Cowboy --
home of Fat Sully's
and Denver Biscuit.
Now it's time for pizza.
What size pizza
should we make?
We do a 26-inch
for slices.
[ Whistles ]
That's a big pie.
Yeah.
So, in the dough is...
Flour, yeast, sugar,
salt, and oil.
So people come in
and get a slice.
They can get it any way
they want it?
Any way they want.
Wow, that's
a good-looking skin.
Whoa.
Hey.
Apparently, you know what to do.
It's like a bed sheet.
Look.
We're not here.
There we go.
Then we're going sauce.
Which you make yourself.
Oh, yeah.
This is a real pro right here.
You see that?
Just starts in the center,
feathers it out.
How much cheese is gonna go
on a pizza this size?
About 1 pound
and 4 ounces.
I'm not gonna weigh it,
though.
'Cause you're living
on the edge.
I'm living on the edge.
All right,
so, first up, sausage.
Italian sausage -- do you guys
make it yourself?
No, we get this
from Clyde's.
He's been in Denver
for about 25 years now.
This is, I think,
the biggest pizza
we've ever made
on "Triple D."
Banana peppers.
Artichokes.
Oh, yeah.
We just put a little
Italian dressing on them
after we chop them.
We can grab some garlic.
Just throw nice little chunks
on it.
What temperature is this oven
running at?
550.
This is gonna be good.
How long?
Uh...six to eight.
That's where the manhole cover
from Flavortown comes from.
We got some fresh basil.
Son of Tatum O'Neal,
this is enormous.
Yeah.
[ Hums "Jaws" theme ]
Sorry.
Dude, too legit.
Mmm.
The sauce is great.
The ingredients
are bountiful.
But, dude, hands down,
that crust is righteous.
[ Crust crunches ]
Could you hear it?
[ Crunching ]
I'll tell you --
I think you guys killed it
with the biscuits.
But that's not only
the biggest pizza
we've ever shot
on "Triple D,"
I honestly got to say --
and this is
regardless of the size --
it's one of
the best pizzas.
You guys are out of control.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Mmm!
I don't even know
where to begin.
It's really, really tasty,
you can tell how fresh it is.
Okay, Brahmo,
tell me about this joint.
It's awesome.
FIERI: This is what people
will wish for in their town.
I want an Atomic Cowboy.
Awesome joint, man.
Thanks for having me.
Killer.
FIERI: Up next, we're heading
to Scottsdale, Arizona...
This should be
interesting.
...where a husband-and-wife
team...
Is that money or what?
Do not take my line.
...is turning the tables
on the first meal of the day.
Call it whatever you want,
just don't call me late for it.
So, I'm cruising
through Scottsdale, Arizona,
to check out a joint
where -- get this --
the wife is a second-generation
Albanian,
the husband is an immigrant
from Mexico.
And together, they got
this breakfast and lunch joint
where they're scratch-making
about 95% of the menu.
This is Perk Eatery.
Table five, order up.
WOMAN: Any time we want
to go for breakfast,
everyone in the family --
"Let's go to Perk."
Fabulous food.
PAULINE: Pancakes,
fresh fruit -- order up.
It's easy to get
a good breakfast.
It's hard to get
a great breakfast.
FIERI: That's why restaurant
vets Pauline and Carmen Martinez
created this place.
We used to go out for breakfast
all the time,
and we could never
find something
like what we would make
at home.
FIERI: So they decided to share
their unique take on breakfast.
We call it classic Americana
with a Southwest kick.
She throws in what she likes.
He throws in what he likes.
FIERI: The result?
A menu full of dynamic dishes
like this one...
PAULINE:
Enchiladas are being plated.
It's really good.
FIERI: ...even though it's got
that one ingredient.
These breakfast enchiladas gonna
involved the "e-g-g" word?
What's "e-g-g"?
[ Crickets chirp ]
Oh, "eggs." I'm sorry.
It does have them.
It doesn't have them
in there.
Oh, okay -- not in there.
On or around them.
Give me the rundown.
First up is the
spicy New Mexico chili sauce.
Chilies with the seeds,
hot water, the salt,
cayenne pepper,
black pepper,
fresh garlic,
honey, chicken base.
Then we have chipotles and adobo
that have already been pureed.
And now we got
to come together
and do a little
[imitates whirring]
A little blend up.
I have to try this.
Mmm. A little yum.
Wow. That's -- ooh.
A little spice.
A little heat in that.
So now we're gonna work
on the pork.
Spice rub is
the first thing we do,
and we're gonna start
with seasoned salt,
fresh ground nutmeg,
paprika,
cumin, dark chili powder,
spicy cayenne,
granulated garlic.
What cut is this?
It's an all-natural,
organic pork shoulder.
Nice.
We only use top quality,
none of that other stuff.
Yeah, with you holding the knife
like that,
you could tell me
that you're an astronaut.
So we're gonna stab it
just so that all of these
yummy spices get in there.
So, we just roll it around
a little bit.
Okay.
Then from there,
we're gonna top it
with our house-made
cilantro jalapeño sauce.
This is
the spicy version.
Now we're gonna add cola,
and we're gonna let this sit
overnight and marinade.
Then roast it...
350 for about 4 1/2 hours.
Dig it.
So we're gonna pull this out,
and we're gonna slice this.
Is that money or what?
Do not go
and take my lines.
Some of that
just breaks apart.
So now what are we gonna do
with it?
We're gonna take it
from here,
and we're gonna grill it
on the flat top
so it gets a nice little
caramelized crisp on it.
And then we'll put it
in the enchilada.
Yes.
Very nice.
And we're
gonna slice it up
so it makes it
a little easier to eat.
And then we're gonna take
these tortillas --
a little bit of homemade
chipotle, ricotta...
zesty black beans,
and then the slow-roasted pork
goes right on top.
Then we're gonna top them
with that spicy New Mexico
chili sauce...
and two incredible,
edible eggs,
and top it with a little bit
of fresh cilantro.
Mmm.
That's really good.
That New Mexican
chili enchilada sauce...
is right on point.
Little bit of heat,
nice little sweetness to it
from that honey.
Call it a breakfast enchilada.
Call it a breakfast burrito.
Call it anything you want,
just don't call me late for it.
Those eggs are a complete
waste of time.
That is just fine
just by itself.
Nicely done.
Awesome.
They are just delicious.
I can't stop stuffing my face.
When this place opened
and we tried it,
it was no turning back.
FIERI:
Kind of like when Pauline
first fell for Carmen,
literally.
He was working as a manager
at another restaurant here,
and there's a little step down
going down into the bar area.
And I had high heels on,
and I almost took a spill,
and he caught my hand.
And he didn't let go
of it?
No.
Honest truth.
Pauline is a genius.
Carmen is right beside her.
They make a blend of flavors
that you'd never think of.
FIERI:
Like this crazy concoction
Pauline threw together
one night.
PAULINE:
Chicken on the Coup.
Chicken on the who?
Coup.
Scratch-made gravy
poured over crispy
sausage-and-sage stuffing.
What are we making?
We are making the
sausage-and-sage stuffing.
Butter, onions, celery.
We're gonna let those sweat down
for a little bit.
Okay.
Add sausage -- give that a stir
to loosen it up a little bit --
salt, black pepper,
and ground sage.
Money.
We have day-old bread.
It's an Italian loaf,
so it really holds together.
So, chicken stock?
Chicken stock.
Okay, so from here, we're gonna
add our cooled sausage mixture.
All righty.
We're gonna combine this --
"Ring Around the Rosie."
Okeydokey.
And we're gonna put it
in the pan to bake.
How long?
About an hour...
at about 400 degrees.
What are we making now?
We are making the
sausage-and-pepper gravy
for the Chicken
on the Coup.
We're gonna start
with reserve bacon grease.
Okay. Very nice.
I'm glad you save that.
Pork sausage again.
And then we have onions.
This gets cooked down.
Then we're gonna add fresh
garlic and chicken base.
Got a little flour
for some roux.
Yeah,
a little bit of flour.
Then we're gonna do
the whole milk.
Nice Vanna White pour.
So we're gonna do black pepper,
granulated garlic,
cayenne pepper
for a little more heat,
and fresh-grated nutmeg.
Then we're gonna let this
thicken up just a little bit.
Then we add
the heavy cream.
Wow, that's a heaping help
of gravy.
No calories here.
That's it.
So, stuffing just came out
of the oven,
so it's nice and hot.
A little soft on the bottom
and crispy on top,
so we're gonna take
a little bit
and put it on the flat top
and let that
get nice and crisp.
So we're gonna take
this crispy stuffing,
and I'll ladle some of this
gravy all the way around it.
And say "goodnight" to Guy,
'cause he's gonna pass out
in the car.
Huevos!
Huevos.
That's it.
Mmm.
I like this little crispy
stuffing thing you just did.
When it's Thanksgiving time,
I always want the stuffing
around the edge of the pan.
Crispy.
Delicious.
Great texture
on the stuffing.
A real gravy -- nice little
black pepper to it.
A big portion -- Thanksgiving
any time of the year.
That's right.
Nicely done.
Chicken on the Coup?
That's it.
There's no bawler on me.
Sorry.
This is good stuff.
MAN:
There's layers to it.
Each time you take a bite,
you taste something different.
All right,
what are we cooking next?
Wine Country French Toast.
This girl's trouble.
Wine Country French Toast
coming up next.
So, of course,
a guy from the wine country
has to come all the way down
to Scottsdale, Arizona,
to Perk Eatery to get...
Wine Country French Toast.
This should be interesting.
We're gonna start
with red wine.
From Italy?
Yes.
Wine Country.
It's a wine country, too.
And then we're gonna do
some balsamic vinegar,
a sprig of rosemary,
and we're gonna let that reduce
until it gets nice and syrupy.
This is getting more odd
as we go.
Once this is reduced,
we're gonna add our maple syrup.
We're gonna let that cook
a little bit longer
till it reduces
about halfway.
This is the Jewish challah
that we use that we hand slice.
Same bakery?
Same bakery.
We're gonna put down a little
bit of clarified butter.
So we're gonna put this
in the egg wash.
That reduces, that cooks,
and we'll put it all together.
Yes.
So we're gonna top this
with brie.
So the brie's on.
Wait till it gets
a little bit melted.
Brie's starting to melt.
We're just gonna drizzle it
over a little bit here.
Just crazy.
Yeah.
And then we have
slow-roasted red grapes.
These are tossed with a little
bit of kosher salt, rosemary,
and a little bit
of clarified butter.
You got a little too much time
on your hands, girl.
You think?
Silence is golden.
You should practice.
[ Laughs ]
This a grown-up breakfast.
You get the richness
of the brie,
cut some of the sweetness with
the tannins of the red wine,
uniqueness of
the roasted grapes.
And the fact that you're brave
enough to put it on the menu,
I think that's what makes
Perk an interesting joint.
Matthew,
Wine Country French Toast.
MAN: I'm telling you,
the French can't make
French Toast like this.
It's very special.
It's a great place to come.
They're getting pretty crowded,
and you can tell why.
Nice job.
Awesome.
So that's it for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Okay, I have a rule.
I don't do shots with people
with better hair than me.
[ Laughter ]
Okay, look at the mustache
and the hair.
I'm already beat at this table.
This is ridiculous.