Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Are you guys excited
at home?
Sure, we're rolling out
killer tacos and sandwiches...
There's a lot
going on here.
...but really, it's a battle
for tot supremacy.
First...
Let me hear
about your magic.
...the 6th Avenue staple
in Tacoma, Washington,
serving moonshine
with two-way pork tacos...
You're out of control.
...and a cheesy take
on the childhood fave.
GRISSOM: We do everything big
around here.
So I'm told.
[ Laughs ]
Then...
So, we're in the thick
of things now.
...a Denver, Colorado, bar
since 1901...
I really like how it just
cleans out the system.
...turning out
homemade pastrami...
That's a new tattoo
right there.
...pig skins...
One of the best things
I've seen on "Triple D."
...and a tot...
This is the moment.
...packing serious
attention to detail.
That's the most
tot-alistic.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here on the north end
of Tacoma, Washington,
on kind of, like,
this peninsula.
There's water all around us.
Now, this is 6th Avenue.
It's kind of like
the party-bar street
to support UPS --
University of Puget Sound.
Now, all of these places
serve some food,
but some of them serve it way
over the top, like this joint --
Dirty Oscar's Annex.
My pan on the hot.
WOMAN:
It's just delicious.
Amazing. Awesome.
FIERI: And while everyone here
has got their own take
on how to describe the menu...
Homestyle high-end.
Pretty much
rock 'n' roll gourmet.
...all agree
25-year-old Aaron Grissom's
going for something different.
Dead Elvis up.
What kind of food
do you describe it as?
New American.
We pretty much take
classic, traditional food
and just spin it way out.
Like how the Tacoma native's
taking tacos to the next level,
with pork he's fixing up
two ways.
Tasso Tacos up.
It's delicious.
It's amazing.
Mmm.
I kind of want
a bite of that.
Every bite
is its own experience.
So, now we're working
on the pork
for the Tasso Pork Taco.
Yep.
Okay.
Sear it on both sides
all the way around, bone in.
Yep.
Got it.
We got mirepoix
with garlic clove here.
Okay.
Our seared pork butt.
So, then, we have a mixture
of chicken and pork stock.
Mmm!
Thyme.
It's "local thyme," too.
I think local "time"
is, uh...
[ Laughs ]
And rosemary.
Thank you very much.
Then, that'll go into the oven
about four or five hours.
What are we making up?
Cure for the tasso.
So, tasso,
the traditional
Louisiana
creole Cajun pork.
So, I got pork shoulder
right here.
Bone removed.
Yep.
We did that.
It has cumin, cracked black
pepper, ground cinnamon,
minced garlic, celery salt,
chili powder, coriander...
...onion powder,
sugar, and salt.
And this gets all mixed up.
This is our curing salt.
[ Whistling ]
We're just gonna
pat this down...
Yep. Absolutely.
....let it set.
It cures for about
four days.
Bring it out,
and then what's the next step?
Just kiss it with smoke.
About an hour.
What kind of smoke?
Apple and cherry.
And then we dry-roast it
in the oven.
Yep.
About 300, four hours.
We've got our pork butt
that's been braised.
That's nice.
Nice and subtle.
So, we have
the shredded tasso.
That's bark plus.
[ Laughs ]
You got to have a good
dental plan, but I dig it.
Okay, so, we have our tasso
and our braised pork butt.
Okay.
I have my pork-braising liquid
for rehydration to order.
We have shredded
Manchego cheese,
which is
a sheep's milk cheese.
This is a big taco,
buddy.
Tasso.
"Tasso" some in there.
Yep.
"Tossing" some in here.
And then I like to just take
that liquid, really get it.
Okay.
We have a roasted jalapeño
and tomato pico de gallo,
pickled radish, apple,
which is local.
I like this.
A little bit
of cilantro,
and then we finish
with the green chili crema.
And that's our tacos.
You're out of control.
Mmm-mm!
Let me break this down.
'Cause there's a lot
going on here.
The texture of the meat
is...
...in my opinion,
so many times not regarded.
But, really, it deserves more
respect, and you give it that.
That pork butt,
the way it's cooked down --
nice and super tender.
Fortifying it with the tasso
with a little bit saltier...
definitely some more crunch
and texture to it.
And then each little component
from the apple to the radish
to a little bit of heat
coming through
that roasted chili crema --
I'm gonna tell you
something, brother.
I've had a few tacos
in my day.
That's a great taco.
Thank you.
You had me at hello.
Excellent job.
Thank you, sir.
Service, please.
There's something about the pork
and the radish together.
It's sweet and salty
and it's amazing.
This is not your average taco.
FIERI: And it ain't
your average bar, either.
This is the only bar in Tacoma
that has moonshine.
FIERI:
That's right.
Moonshine -- mixed up
in 12 off-the-hook drinks.
And when we come back,
they find a partner
with Aaron's take on
the one, the only tater tot.
Do the laws of physics
cease to exist in my kitchen?
Yeah.
FIERI:
"Triple D" is at Dirty Oscar's
Annex in Tacoma, Washington...
Service, please.
...where my man,
Chef Aaron Grissom,
thinks he's cracked
the holy grail
of deep-fried finger foods.
An utterly amazing soft potato
filled with
an amazing creamy Parmesan.
Just melts in your mouth.
What are these called,
anyways?
Parmesan tots.
I think everybody
in their culinary career,
at one time or another,
has tried to make the bomb tot.
It's hard to get them as good
as they manufacture them,
so let me hear
about your magic.
Okay, so, we have boiled
russet potatoes from Idaho.
We just want to let them
hang out,
keeping some texture
to them,
but enough mash on them
that they'll go together.
Yep. Absolutely.
Okay.
We have
our Parmesan cheese.
Whoa.
Our white cheddar.
Yeah, quality check.
Provolone.
Our IQF hash browns.
IQF --
Individually Quick Frozen.
There's something
about freezing stuff
and drawing the moisture
out of them,
and I have done
hash brown experiments
at my house
a million times.
You can never get them
that good.
And that's the sad thing
of it.
It's like,
why do I not --
Do the laws of physics cease
to exist in my kitchen?
Yeah.
I just kind of mix it up
just a touch.
We have our panko.
And that's another part
of our binder.
We have cubed Havarti.
And some AP --
All-purpose flour.
Yep. Absolutely.
All right,
so, we mix them,
we let it rest for a day,
and then we form them.
So, you're gonna mix this,
just let this congeal.
A little bit. Yeah.
It just does the magic.
Yeah.
Okay, so, these are cold,
had a chance to seize up.
Now you'll make them
into your --
Cylindrical.
That's a big'un.
We do everything big
around here.
So I'm told.
[ Laughs ]
Okay,
so, we knock these out.
Oil temperature -- 350?
Yes.
And go down for...
It's roughly two minutes.
Tasting-tots time.
I really don't know about the
piece of butter lettuce there.
[ Laughs ]
Just act like
it's not there.
Ooh!
Creamy, cheesy totness.
Sun-dried tomato ranch.
Yep.
Mmm.
Here's the deal.
Most tots that
I've had people try to make
just don't really
have the texture.
You don't feel that little bit
of that potato crunch.
They're usually just soggy,
battered, fried nuggets
of hash browns.
This right here, this is on
its way to the real deal.
It's not exactly it,
but that's the beauty of it,
because this is handmade
and not processed.
Yep.
Dude, rocked the house
on that one.
Thank you.
Service, please.
Tell me about the tots.
They'll change your life.
WOMAN: I mean,
it's potatoes and cheese,
and they're fried, so,
I mean, that's literally
the three best things.
Oh, my dad.
A lot of flavors
and a lot of rich food,
and all handmade,
scratch-made in this kitchen.
Again, killer.
Thank you, man.
FIERI: Up next...
Wow. That is funky.
...we're headed
to Denver, Colorado...
The flavor jets
just turned on.
...for an old-school dive bar
with serious culinary chops.
That's about as righteous
as you'll find 'em.
I'm here in
the Highlands neighborhood,
about a mile from downtown
Denver, Colorado,
and about a mile away
from Citizen Pictures,
the folks that happen to produce
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives,"
but don't let those details
confuse you.
I'm here to check out
a joint that I hear
has the most real-deal,
off-the-hook,
outrageous bar food
you can find.
This is Highland Tavern.
Stupid Burger
in the window.
Much more upscale than what
you would consider a local bar.
Not a Philly.
MAN: The attention
to having higher ingredients
in a dive-bar feel.
FIERI: Just when owners
Brian Sommatino and Andy Stutz
had in mind
when they bought this old joint.
The building we're in is
an old Coors Brewing building?
Yeah, built in 1901
by Coors.
It's been a bar pretty much
from 1901 till now,
minus prohibition.
So, they kept the suds flowing
and hired fine-dining chef
Jeremy McMinn
to build up the menu.
Every dish has a little
something added to it
that just makes you
remember it.
Like a pork shank
braised in ancho chili,
spare ribs
glazed with Dr Pepper,
and house-made pastrami
he's dropping
on this killer sandwich.
McMINN:
Bombshell up.
It is just marvelous.
So, I assume from pink salt
and a big, fat brisket,
we're gonna get into
some kind of corned beef
or a pastrami or something
along that line?
Yeah, we're making
some pastrami.
Okay.
Get it going.
We're gonna trim
this guy up.
Just taking enough off
that it doesn't become messy.
Yeah.
Trim done.
We're gonna cut this
in half.
There we go.
All right,
we got kosher salt.
Some brown sugar.
White sugar.
Some pink salt.
Get some honey
going into this.
Dump our water in here.
Sachet bag.
Got some hickory spice,
garlic in there.
We'll bring this
up to a boil.
We're gonna cool
this brine down.
I really like how it just
cleans out the system.
Cool this down
with some ice.
You go about 50/50,
so this will cool it down,
because otherwise
you're gonna poach it,
and you're gonna let this brine
for seven days?
15 days.
15 days?!
Wow, this thing's
gonna be neon pink.
Yeah.
Weight it down
with this plate.
There you go.
I love it.
Off to the walk-in?
Off to the walk-in.
Great.
All right, so, we've brined,
rinsed it off,
now go into dry rub.
Granulated garlic,
ground coriander,
and ground black pepper.
Give this a little stir.
Apply the rub
liberally.
It's a good-looking rub.
Now, how long is this gonna
go here on the Big Chief?
We do it
for about four hours.
FIERI: I mean,
the flavor's in this.
The curing process
is done.
Now we're just gonna
put some smoke flavor to it,
and then for the final process
of serving,
you're gonna steam it
for service.
Correct.
Okay.
So, you're pulling it
from the smoke.
Now we're gonna finish
the cooking process
in the steam, in the oven
for how long?
McMINN: It's about three
and a half hours.
Okay.
This is gonna go in the walk-in
and cool overnight
before we slice it.
Okay.
So, we're in the thick
of things now.
I should probably just try this
for scientific reasons.
That'll be fine.
Mmm.
Very nice.
Scien-ticious.
First, we're gonna butter
and toast our rye bread.
Drop our pastrami.
Put our Swiss cheese
down.
Pastrami jus.
Melts that cheese
right into it.
Rye bread
gets a little brown mustard.
Pastrami's hot,
cheese is melted.
Goes on the sandwich.
Plate this up over here.
Those are hot.
Over-medium egg
if you're smart.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Gets a little slaw.
It's the Bombshell.
That's a new tattoo
right there.
Wow.
Mmm.
Chew.
Breathe.
[ Mumbling ]
I know.
I've eaten at some of
the greatest delis
in the world,
and that's about as righteous
as you'll find them.
Awesome.
It's the right mustard.
The meat's super tender.
Not too much smoke,
not too much pepper, coriander,
not too salty.
I mean, just
a package deal, man.
That is...
an incredibly righteous
pastrami sandwich.
Excellent job, brother.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Mmm.
Mmm!
I've never had anything
like this before.
This is by far one of
my favorite sandwiches around.
WOMAN:
Good people, really good food.
Just a wonderful place to be.
It's almost like
having a party at home.
Everybody knows everybody.
Everybody knows the bartenders.
FIERI:
In fact, the place is so local,
owners Brian and Andy
plucked Jeremy from a barstool.
He was a regular.
He lived about a block away.
Came here after work
to have his beer to go home,
and I asked him to be the chef
and he said yes.
That was like
hitting the lottery.
Yes.
And they hit the jackpot
when Jeremy
showed he could tackle
the Everest of bar food...
Tavern Tots.
...the homemade tater tot.
By far, the best things
I've ever found
in my entire life.
Do I need
to freeze-dry them?
to dehydrate them?
What exactly --
Eventually I just gave up
and we made up our own thing.
All right.
Well, let's see how you do it.
We're gonna cook
the potatoes.
Cold water.
We're gonna bring these up
to just barely a simmer.
Okay.
And then even
the heat out on it,
and just let them sit.
It usually takes about 40
minutes until they're al dente.
Al dente -- No, okay.
Yeah, that's probably
a pretty good description.
So, do you have a timer
on this?
No.
Awesome.
So, there's a variable
here.
Yeah.
All right.
So, we got our parsley,
cooked potato
that's just cooked enough
that it'll still make shreds.
Yeah.
So, hash brown-ish.
Hash brown-ish, yeah.
There you go.
Ooh!
It's like a snow blower.
So, if you're
a breakfast house,
you would die to have
hash coming out like that.
A little bit of grit
to it,
so it's not completely finished,
and this is the foundation.
That's it.
I love it.
Now what's the process?
Then we got to mix in
our dry ingredients.
Salt?
Salt.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion.
Cayenne pepper.
Nice.
The key is there's a lot
of nooks and crannies
to all that --
All those different pieces
of potato,
so the more evenly
you can distribute this...
Okay.
We're gonna add tamari
to our eggs.
Really?
Yeah.
So, that little bit of egg's
gonna help bind it.
Yeah.
I'm excited.
Are you guys excited
at home?
Now, we got to form these,
freeze them,
form them, set them up.
Form them
and drop them.
Like it's hot?
They will be hot
once we've dropped them.
Okay. What size tot
do you make?
It's about an ounce
and a quarter.
Okay.
Cook them on 350?
375.
Till they're GBD.
That's golden brown
and delicious.
I pick it up.
A little salt on these.
There it is.
Small order of tots.
This is the moment.
[ Angelic vocalizing ]
Good separation.
Looking good so far.
That's what you're looking for
in a tot.
Out of all the house-made tots
I've had...
mine included...
that's the most
tot-alistic.
[ Laughs ]
This is ridiculous.
Way to hammer that out.
Thanks.
In the world
of "Triple D,"
that's probably one of the best,
if not the best rendition
of a homemade tot.
Thanks.
Nice job.
And great seasoning.
[ Laughs ]
Watch out
for this guy.
I like to think of them
as, like, tots redefined.
WOMAN: This will ruin tots
for everywhere else
because they are really
just the best.
Okay.
So, this has been pretty much
a ridiculous visit.
We've had
the bomb pastrami,
we have declassified
the tots,
and now when we come back,
we're hanging out here
in Denver, Colorado.
We are going to make --
Shh! Shh!
See you in a little it.
Really hold them on the edge.
Right on the edge.
So, welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Denver, Colorado.
We're in the Highland
neighborhood at...
McMINN:
The Highland Tavern.
Very nice.
We've done tots,
we've done pastrami,
and now we will venture
into --
'Cause there's nothing
that this guy won't touch.
What are we doing now?
We're gonna make
our pork rinds.
Pork rinds
in the window.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Give me the rundown.
Got some raw pigskins.
Now, these are pigskins
from the --
Belly skin.
Belly skin, primarily,
is what you want to use in this?
This is where the bacon
has been taken out,
just to give you
some reference,
and you are now
going to...
We're gonna drop this
in some boiling water.
Drop it.
Drop it
like it's skin.
Great. That's a little
"Silence of the Lamb"-y for me.
So, you got to cook this
through.
Got four hours
at a full-on boil.
Salted?
No salt.
All right.
Wow.
That is funky, man.
Now you'll cut them into chunks,
pieces, strips?
Little strips.
Okay.
So, this little
munchkin dehydrator
is gonna do
all the work.
It's gonna do
How long
are these gonna go?
Set it and forget it
for about 26 and a half hours.
Not 27?
Not 27.
Not 25.
26.
26 and a...
Half.
When you dehydrate it
and take all that moisture out,
that's what gives them
the chance to really puff up?
Yeah.
All right.
Load 'em up,
shut 'em down.
26 and a half hours,
and here we go.
That's it.
Genius.
Okay.
They're ready
to come out.
Dehydrated pig skin.
Really?
Yeah.
Like, hard plastic.
So, now we're gonna go
to the fryer.
Let's go.
Whoa!
It's amazing every single time
you do it, too --
doesn't get old.
That is --
I'm telling you,
I have seen some cool things
on "Triple D."
That might be
in the top 10 coolest.
Bring over
those mouth killers.
Wow.
Hot!
Okay. Next.
We're gonna make
the chili lime-salt mix.
We got our lime salt.
Korean chili flake.
Chili powder.
A little mix.
Season 'em.
That's ridiculous.
There you go.
Look at that.
That's a lot of work,
buddy.
[ Crunching loudly ]
Dude, you kill this.
Thanks.
This is how they were
to be appreciated.
Fresh, crispy, light,
not dense.
The flavor jets
just turned on.
They're trying
to shut down
that flavor fire
I got in my mouth.
You want another one?
Maybe a little Tebow.
Hang on a second.
That is ridiculous.
I don't say this often,
but that's the best chicharrone
I've ever had.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
I'm really taken back,
man.
MAN:
I love the pork rinds.
I think they should be
prescribed to me by my doctor.
Magic in the mouth.
These are great.
Pretty ridiculous.
Yes.
Just keep talking. I'm gonna
just keep eating these.
One of the best "Triple D"
experiences I've had.
And I've seen a lot.
Okay?
There we go.
Thanks, man.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughter ]