Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Pica'pun.
...we got to watch
what we say...
What was that again?
...'cause we're getting
a little fresh...
Schweinebauch.
...in Portland, Oregon.
This is gonna get
gnar-ly.
The German sausage stop...
Whoa. whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
...cranking out
real-deal links...
It's like he's wrestling
an orange anaconda.
...with beyond-authentic cuts.
Expect this at the Fieri house
for Christmas.
And in San Francisco,
California...
Go get 'em.
I'll be back here.
...a Venezuelan joint...
A little bit of Venezuela,
a little bit of San Francisco.
...taking on my taste buds...
Outrageous outrageous.
...and working my vocabulary.
Cachapa.
Exactly.
Time to cachapa.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here
in Northern California
in one of my favorite cities,
San Francisco.
Now, it's been a while
since we've had
the Venezuelan specialty,
arepas, on the show.
You know, we're talking about
those grilled corn pockets
that are stuffed with goodness.
So you know I am stoked
to find out
right here
in the Mission District,
there's a joint
that's rocking the arepas.
This is Pica Pica.
We got
a pulled-pork arepa.
This is one of the only things
that I crave.
Nachos Pica Pica.
Vegeteriana cachapa.
I'll eat everything on the menu,
twice.
FIERI:
That's music to the ears
of Caracas native
Adriana Lopez Vermut,
the rockin' chef and owner
who opened her first place
with her dad in '08.
And now they dish out
this killer Venezuelan food
at three of their NorCal spots.
I never even thought
to try Venezuelan food,
and it's
one of my favorites now.
FIERI: No doubt --
when it means getting to eat
this corn-pocket wonder.
Arepa Pabellón!
FIERI: Arepa...
Pabellón.
Uh-huh.
We're gonna make
the beef.
That's called
"carne mechada."
Carne...
Mechada.
It means "shredded."
So, we're gonna add
our cilantro...
onions...
red peppers...
garlic...
salt...
...beef.
What kind of beef?
Chuck.
Okay.
And then water.
And that's it?
And that's it.
And that will boil
for a good four hours.
Just let it beef.
Let it beef.
Then we go --
We tackle that.
The Pabellón sauce.
Pabellón.
All right. Oil.
This is where we're gonna start
with our sofrito.
Sofrito base.
You know sofrito?
Oh, I love sofrito.
Onion.
Garlic.
Green onions.
Red bell pepper.
Okay.
Sugarcane. We really like
to cook with sugarcane.
Natural sugar?
Yeah.
It's better for you.
Cumin.
Worcestershire sauce.
What was that again?
Salsa Inglesa. You know
how we call it in Spanish?
I know Salsa Inglesa, yeah.
Worcestershire sauce --
'cause, believe me,
nobody can say that.
No one can say it
in the United States anyway.
Hot sauce?
Pica'pun.
What is pica'pun?
Taste it.
You'll find out.
It's our signature hot sauce.
Ohh.
Mm.
You want to lick it
while I cook?
Mustard.
Salt.
Ketchup.          Ketchup.
And tomatoes.
So, we're gonna let this cook
for about another hour?
Yeah.
Our beef is ready.
Yep.
So, now we're gonna just pour
the beef onto the sauce.
So, we're gonna let this cook
for another hour?
Mm-hmm.
And meanwhile, we'll make
the arepa while it's cooking?
Uh-huh.
All right.
So, you take warm water.
Salt.
Yes.
This is the ingredient
for Venezuelans.
A little bit of corn flour --
Harina P.A.N.
Okay.
Vegetable shortening.
And do you eyeball this?
It's by feel.
And now it's ready.
Okay.
So, now what do we do?
First, make the balls.
Look at the size
of this thing.
That's good.
Okay.
Now we got them formed.
They're formed,
and now let's go cook them.
So, you just put them
on the flattop.
Okay.
A little crust on.
Then you transfer that
over to the grill to mark them.
Let's plate one.
So, first,
you have your pocket.
Black bean paste.
Okay.
Then our fabulous
carne mechada.
Tajadas --
sweet plantains.
A little sweetness
with the plantain.
Uh-huh.
And then you sprinkle it
with queso fresco
which is
a little bit of salt.
And this is
the Venezuela in a pocket,
arepa Pabellón.
You bite into this and you get
the exterior, the crunch,
and then it's creamy,
and really creamy.
Mmm.
Wow.
I've had a lot of arepas.
That's the biggest one
by far.
But that meat --
it's outrageous.
The depth of flavor
in this --
You get sweet, you get tang,
you get sour.
And then you clean
your palate
with a little bit
of this slaw.
I don't know
what to tell you, girl.
That's outrageous.
I mean, like,
outrageous outrageous.
WOMAN: It's the right amount
of sweet, a little bit of spice.
And then the queso fresco
is the perfect finish.
FIERI: And there's no reason
to sit out this meal,
'cause the whole menu --
get this --
is gluten-free.
It's gluten-free
without manipulation.
You can come here,
get something
that was meant
to taste this way,
and also enjoy the fact
that it's good for you.
FIERI:
I'm in San Francisco
hanging at a funky little joint
called Pica Pica
having some fantastic
Venezuelan food.
I don't know
that I can eat any more,
but I can assure you
that when you come back,
she's gonna make me
eat more.
I'll see you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
This is "Triple D" hanging out
at Pica Pica in San Francisco.
What are we into now?
Cachapa.
Exactly.
Time to cachapa.
It's a sweet corn crepe.
Okay.
Now the sweet corn.
Corn flour --
Harina P.A.N.
Then sugar and salt.
Okay.
So, you'll notice,
no water.
Got it.
It's a pretty thick
batter, uh?
And then the corn
has its juice.
So, the batter's done,
and that'll make
the cachapa?
That's right.
But before we do that?
We've gonna be making
the marinade for the tofu.
Venezuelan tofu?
A little bit of Venezuela,
a little bit of San Francisco.
People here love tofu.
That's how it works
here at Pica Pica. All right.
Cilantro.
White onion.
Dry oregano.
Thyme.
Whoa.
Bay leaves, comino.
Nice.
Black pepper, salt, honey.
And?
Red wine vinegar.
Red wine vinegar?
Mm-hmm.
This is all the marinade
for the tofu?
That's it.
Okay.
All right.
Go get 'em.
I'll be back here.
After this is done,
we're gonna put it in the
Vitamix so that it's pureed.
Girl, you can make some sauces
and marinades.
Wow!
Now the pressed tofu
goes down into the marinade.
Oh, that's awesome.
How long's it go?
Overnight.
And this gets served
inside of the...
Cachapa.
All right.
Let's do it.
Let's go.
You take your muñequita
batter down.
So cachapa's being made.
Let's grill the tofu.
Sizzle, sizzle.
You can see
everything dances here.
Come on down
for the dancing tofu.
So, grill both sides?
Yep.
Then we put it together?
And then we're gonna
assemble it.
Very nice.
First, we put a little bit of
ensalada verde
with a little bit
of house vinaigrette.
So, then we have
our cachapa.
Crazy.
First off, black bean paste,
which we call moreno.
Garlic aioli.
Then you take
your grilled tofu...
sweet plantains...
your avocado.
Geez.
Voilà.
Wow.
That is crazy.
Isn't it?
The cachapa...
...on the sweeter side,
but really nice texture
in that you can taste the corn
being ground up.
Kind of like
a corn salad.
But then you get
a little bit of the crisp,
a little bit of the burnt,
a little bit of the char
kind of like you roasted corn
on a barbecue.
The tofu's
nice and meaty.
My sister was a big vegetarian,
my sister Morgan.
This would be the kind of dish
she would love.
There's great texture.
There's uniqueness.
There's depth of flavor.
That's outrageous.
Sweet and crispy on the outside,
yet gooey on the inside.
I got to tell you, girl,
an outrageous experience.
Awesome.
The food's dynamite.
Your personality
is bouncing off the screen.
I mean, you've got
three of these joints.
People are gonna be lining up
to come find them
because it is
the real deal.
FIERI: Coming up...
It's a meat slam dunk.
...we're headed
to Portland, Oregon...
Hit it, boss.
...for serious sausages...
It's like the Iron Man
sausage maker.
...and a big-time bologna bill.
Bologna's a nice, fine,
blended meat.
You should have almost had
an ascot on.
Bologna is
a fine blended meat.
It's a beautiful day here
on the southeast side
of Portland, Oregon.
I'm in the Brooklyn neighborhood
to check out a joint
that I hear is doing
real-deal German sausage.
This is Edelweiss
Sausage & Delicatessen.
WOMAN: Currywurst.
Row upon row of meat --
salamis, liverwursts,
blood sausage.
FIERI: They've got --
now get this --
over 120 different types of
German sausage and lunch meat.
All their food is high-quality
and top-notch.
They use
the best ingredients.
It's very authentic.
It should be.
Founder George Baier grew up
and learned the trade in Berlin
before opening this joint
in '76.
In '99,
he passed the sausage baton
to his two sons, Tony and Tom,
who flat-out ran with it.
How many pounds of sausage
will you do in a year?
We'll do a couple thousand
in a week.
So, it's not out of line
to say that you can be
at 150,000 to 200,000 pounds
of sausage a year?
Yeah.
FIERI: Including
one of my favorites from Italy.
The Italian red wine salami,
it's just right.
So,
this is Italian salami.
We're gonna start
with the pork fat.
This is all frozen.
This is gonna get
gnar-ly.
All right.
Nice, fine dice.
Look at that!
We're gonna add
the beef to it.
What cuts?
Bottom rounds.
Yep.
This is a curing salt.
Just some real fine sugar,
some salt, some Morton salt,
and then the dextrose.
We'll add
the white pepper...
Don't breathe that.
...the ground fennel...
black pepper...
whole fennel...
Nice.
...juniper berry...
crushed garlic...
whole bottle of I-talian
red wine.
I-talian!
We'll hand-mix it
a little,
make sure everything's
well-incorporated.
Look at that texture.
So, we'll take it from here,
go to here?
We'll load it
right into the stuffer. See?
Stays nice and together.
That's it?
Yep.
Putting that right in.
Hit it, boss.
Synthetic casing.
Then we give it
a little clip.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Don't get your thumb in
on that one!
That is awesome!
Is this gonna shrink up at all
when it hangs?
It'll lose about
20% of its weight.
The casing
will pull with it.
Killer.
Okay.
Give this a shot.
All right.
I'm gonna wear half of this.
I can already feel it.
Pull!
Perfect.
Nice.
This will dry up well.
We'll hang them
on some smoke sticks.
So, we're on like this?
Yep.
We'll let it cure and hang
for a couple of days,
and then we'll throw it
in the cold smoker
for probably two days.
And then we'll put them in our
little drying room over there.
So, now it's gonna spend
two to three more weeks,
and then
it'll really dry out.
So, this is one of the bad boys
that's been done.
Dried and smoked.
Smell that.
[ Thuds ]
[ Sniffs ]
[ Chuckles ]
You have to take that casing
off, put it on our slicer.
There we go.
Wow! Mmm!
It's tender.
Great balance.
Still has some moisture in it,
although you call it dry.
Yeah.
Not a lot of smoke, even though
he did put smoke on it.
The texture's really nice.
There's still some chew to it.
I would do damage on a deli
with this.
[ Chuckles ]
WOMAN: You can taste the meat,
but it's not overpowering.
It's very flavorful.
I enjoy coming here
for the shopping.
FIERI:
Oh, the grocery store?
Have you seen
the wall of chocolate?
MAN: Products that I've never
been able to find anywhere else,
just as they do
back in Germany.
FIERI:
They're even breathing new life
into one lucky lunch meat.
Standard bologna is just not
what we're talking about.
FIERI:
We're talking upper crust here.
Bologna's a nice, fine,
blended meat.
You should have almost had
an ascot on.
Bologna is a fine
[Inhales sharply]
blended meat.
That they're serving up
15 different ways.
Combinations you wouldn't
necessarily think about.
What bologna
is this going to be?
This is gonna be
the roasted garlic
and fresh rosemary bologna.
Very nice.
This is nice and fresh,
lean beef.
What cut?
Chuck.
Pork shoulder.
Got it.
Wow.
That is fine.
On the first press,
to be shooting it through
like that...
Next up, nice, lean,
hand-trimmed pork shoulder.
You got the back fat,
roasted garlic,
and the cornucopia
of spices.
We're gonna start
with the back fat.
We're gonna dice it.
Here in the monster?
Yep.
Next is
the ground meats.
The chuck
and the pork shoulder.
Now ice?
We've got to keep it cold
when it's blending.
If it gets hot,
it'll separate.
Add our seasonings --
curing salts,
lemon powder.
Give it a little zing.
Okay.
Garlic powder.
Fresh garlic.
Little bit of sugar.
White pepper.
Smoked paprika.
Ground mustard.
Now we'll click it up
on high.
[ Machine whirring loudly ]
Sounds like
an airplane propeller.
That is gnarly.
More ice.
We'll add the seasonings.
Rosemary.
Mustard seed.
Now we're gonna add
that coarse pork.
Of course we are.
The roasted garlic.
I'm gonna hand mix it
a little bit first.
Okay.
And I'll run it
one time around.
Just enough to incorporate this,
not to break it down?
And there we go. It's ready
for loading and stuffing.
And we'll ball it up.
Wow.
Then just plop it in.
It's a meat slam dunk.
What kind of casing
is this?
That's a synthetic.
Soaked in water?
Soaked in water.
I mean, I can't wait
to watch this.
It's like he's wrestling
an orange anaconda.
These guys
are a little bigger.
So, what happens
from here?
Load them
into the kettle.
We'll cook them
for about three hours.
About 160 degrees
of water.
When they come up to an internal
temperature of 152 degrees,
we'll put them
in an ice bath.
Stop the cooking process?
Yep.
How long will they stay
in the cooler?
Usually overnight,
and then they're ready
for slicing.
Then they're ready to roll.
Look at that.
Ohh.
Seriously?!
Who made this one up?
That was one of mine.
I'm just gonna go ahead
and build myself a sandwich.
[ Chuckles ]
Look at that.
Hmm?
Mmm. Killer!
You get the richness
of the garlic,
a little herbaceous coming
through from the rosemary.
Mmm.
That's killer.
Nice job.
Excellent.
The garlic rosemary bologna.
It's amazing.
This is as close
as you're gonna get to Germany
without getting a passport.
[ Snaps finger ]
Snap!
FIERI:
And when we come back,
we're going even deeper
into the sausage empire.
Schweinebauch.
This you don't want to miss.
I don't even know what to say.
FIERI: At Edelweiss
Sausage & Delicatessen
in Portland, Oregon,
there are over 120
different reasons to stop by.
We sell enough sausage
to be a sausage empire.
Including one
you got to say out loud.
Schweinebauch.
I'm familiar with this.
Pork belly.
We're gonna stuff it
with sausage.
Seriously?
Yeah, and roast it
in the oven.
So, you're gonna cut
right in between?
Actually, I'll go right inside.
Pocket it.
You're going that way?
Yep.
[ Whistles ]
So, you're gonna make
a log o' pork?
Yeah.
The key is
not to poke through it.
Easier said than done.
What kind of sausage are we
gonna be stuffing inside of it?
It'll be a bologna
with coarse pork.
All right.
There we go.
Now we got to brine
this guy.
Then stuff it?
Yep.
Got it.
Yeah. All right.
Use some curing salts.
Gonna make up a nice brine.
This is gonna brine
for about a week.
So, we're really
making bacon?
Yes. Exactly.
Now we're gonna stuff it
with the bologna,
with the coarse, lean pork.
So, it just doesn't have the
roasted garlic or the rosemary.
Exactly.
Got it.
In we go.
And it's like we're packing
our lunch to go.
Here we go, kids.
Bye-bye.
Work that down in.
We use the hook
to close it up.
Close it?
Yeah.
This is awesome.
Expect this at the Fieri house
for Christmas.
Look at that thing
right there.
How long's
this gonna cook?
About three hours.
At what temp?
250 degrees.
250,
so the bacon will cook nice,
you'll baste it
with its juices.
Let's see it.
All right.
Like butter.
O-M-G.
I don't even know
what to say.
So, not just wrapped in bacon,
but cooked in its own bacon.
That's out of bounds.
The crunch on the outside of it,
getting that texture,
and it's tender on the inside
like pâté.
It's awesome.
The saltiness of it,
the creamy, the texture.
Just the fact that it cooked
inside the big bacon.
You're gonna have to start
a self-help group.
These guys work hard
to make sure this tastes
as good as it is.
FIERI: They make it all,
they serve it all,
grocery store,
the whole thing.
Are you blown away
by that?
I am.
This is great.
Your dad should be really proud.
This is one of the best
I've seen. Nice job.
Excellent. Thank you.
Really. Amazing job.
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Which one's your favorite?
The beef, of course.
But not with your fork.
Fingers, please.
I was just checking
if it was hot.
[ Fork clatters ]
Who would eat these with a fork?
What an idiot.
Seriously.
Hot.
[ Laughter ]