Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Can someone please
dim the lights?
Mind your P's
and forget about the Q's...
Pure elegance.
Dig it.
...'cause it's peppers,
pork, and poutine.
Yes, 'cause that's exactly
what I expected next.
In Phoenix, Arizona...
Meet my "sista"
from another "mista."
...real-deal,
authentic Mexican...
My mouth is having
just some complete meltdown.
...with straight-up flavors
from around the country.
Say hello
to my little pig.
And in Toronto, Canada...
This is fancy funky.
...the Middle Eastern diner...
[ Whistles ]
...with a Canadian kick.
Run by a husband-and-wife team
that knows the rules
of the restaurant.
Did you just tell him
to get his elbows off the table?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Spray can hissing ]
I'm here at Phoenix, Arizona,
to check out a joint
where we're gonna get some food
that you'd totally expect
in this town.
That's right -- Mexican food.
But let me warn you,
as I have been warned,
don't walk into this joint
asking for any fajitas
or chimichangas,
and please don't ask
for chips and salsa.
What you should expect to get,
though,
is some real-deal,
Mexican cultural cuisine.
This is Barrio.
I got a cochinita pibil
coming up. Let's go!
It's not like what you think
is Mexican food.
WOMAN:
It tastes like it's home cooking
from some little village
in Mexico
that I'll never get to go to.
FIERI: Places that
Silvana Salcido Esparza
knows well.
WOMAN #2: She's traveled
extensively throughout Mexico,
and she's compiled a lot
of recipes and flavors
from all of her travels.
FIERI: Combine that with
classical French techniques
that she picked up
at culinary school
and you've got
the Barrio Café...
Camarón borracho on the line.
FIERI: ...where she's been
flexing her culinary muscles
since 2002...
Chiles en nogada
coming up right now.
FIERI:
...with dishes like this one
from the state of Puebla.
The chiles en nogada.
Chiles en nogada.
And what does that
stand for?
"Nogada" is walnut sauce.
But I don't put walnuts
in my sauce.
We're not gonna put
any walnuts?
We're gonna put almonds?
It kind of changes it.
Olive oil, shallots.
A little garlic.
Absolutely.
Season with salt
and pepper.
Deglaze
with a little white wine?
Just a little white wine.
We're gonna let this reduce.
Fresh thyme.
And I dig these shades,
by the way.
You like them?
They're gangster.
You know, I'm a little bit
gangster about everything.
I see the way that you are.
Look at the ink.
Tell me
that's not crazy, huh?
Meet my "sista"
from another "mista."
A little heavy cream.
Just a little bit.
A little bit of sugar,
just to sweeten up
the candy here.
And then we're gonna go
to the almonds,
and I'm gonna crush 'em.
Mind if I taste it?
Go right ahead.
We should've made
about another gallon of that.
What are we making now?
The stuffing
for the chiles en nogada.
So, we're just gonna throw a
little bit of chicken in here.
Kosher salt,
a little pepper.
I like pepper.
We're just gonna
cook this down.
Red onions,
a little bit of shallots.
I don't see shallots
a lot in Mexican food.
That's my
classically trained...
Okay.
I love what it does
to the food.
Garlic.
Add apples, pears.
Here's my Anglo influence --
craisins, apricots, golden
raisins, tomato paste --
and that's my touch.
Deglaze with red wine.
I'm gonna add
a little bit of sugar.
I like that car of yours,
by the way.
Not bad, huh?
But you know what?
It might be on blocks
right now.
It's okay.
I need to change
those tires out anyways.
Let's finish it up
with chopped pecans.
And we have some walnuts.
Add cilantro.
This is gonna rock. Mmm!
Almost ready to stuff.
Stuff.
We roast chiles poblanos.
So, you roasted
the pepper off.
Now I'm peeling
all the skin off.
Which takes a little bit
of that bitterness out.
Think about
like caramelization.
I have that stuffing.
There we go.
Then I'm gonna take this
beautiful almond nogada sauce.
We're gonna represent
something beautiful here --
the colors
of the Mexican flag.
White of the queso fresco,
the pomegranate for the red,
cilantro for green.
We're good to go.
Got to get some
of that pepper in there.
This is real deal.
This is old-school.
This is --
This is delicious.
Just all the textures,
the flavors, the depth,
and you have
all the nuances.
The complexities,
the roasted pepper,
tenderness of the chicken.
You get some of the little
dried fruit coming through,
and you get a little burst
coming from the pomegranate.
I mean, just all of it.
You rocked that one.
Orale.
Very nice.
I love something
with a little bite,
and it had the perfect amount.
I could've eaten two more.
It's an experience
that's more than
just going to get a bite to eat.
WOMAN #2: They're very much
about community
and supporting local artists.
If you look at, in the art
of Mexico, it's very bright.
Then you look at the ingredients
of the food.
It's vivid. It's robust.
FIERI:
And that all comes together
in this Baja-style dish.
You have the tilapia
wrapped in banana leaves.
That's a fabulous dish.
Mmm.
Looking good -- banana leaves,
fish, achiote paste.
We're gonna do
zarandeado.
It's a Baja dish.
We're just gonna do a little
lemon, a little naranja.
Now, this right here
is the achiote paste.
Correct.
And you'll find this a lot
of times in Latin markets.
It gives
that nice, red hue.
Now watch what happens here
with the banana leaves.
You're gonna toast up
the banana leaf?
I'm just gonna make it
pliable.
Nice.
Oh, you're good.
So, this is
nice and pliable.
Now we're gonna take
the fish.
Add a little slurry.
Put it in there
and spread it out.
So, you get the citrus,
you get all that color.
Absolutely.
I use kosher salt,
a little black pepper,
just a little citrus
from the orange.
A little lemon, some garlic,
and then I have some onion.
And we're ready
to grill it.
Presentation side down.
Seven minutes.
So, it'll steam all
the ingredients inside of it
because of the moisture
of the banana leaf.
What are we gonna serve
this with?
Just got a little bit
of calabaza real quick.
Some squash.
There we go.
What you do is just peel it away
like a little gift.
Tilapia is not typically
very fat,
but it is
a very widely used fish.
Roasting it in this banana leaf
with all that flavor,
a lot of moisture,
this is the way to go.
Mmm! If you get a chance
to come try this,
you will get a whole nother
experience and exposure
to what Mexican food
really is --
real Mexican food,
cultural Mexican food.
It's packaged, baby.
Mmm!
SALCIDO ESPARZA:
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Let's get this out of here!
The flavors are just wonderful.
So, here's the deal.
This has been
an outstanding visit.
You got one more
up your sleeve for me?
We're gonna go
to the other coast.
I'm hanging out
in Phoenix, Arizona,
at a killer
Mexican restaurant.
This is Barrio.
We'll see you in a little bit.
"Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"
going real-deal Mexican
in Phoenix.
You got to come to Barrio
because this is
real-deal Mexican, right?
Absolutely.
MAN:
Just the flavor in everything.
Just got so much style.
I always feel like
I'm at home here.
MAN #2:
You're getting a lot of flavors
from a lot of different regions
across Mexico.
FIERI:
Including a classic version
of Yucatán's pulled pork.
This is called
cochinita pibil.
"Cochinita" means
"little pig."
"Pibil" means "under earth"
or "pit" in Mayan.
Okay.
So, I'm just gonna take
a little bit of this fat off.
Why are you moving
back there?
Well, because I don't --
Listen.
My dad's told me you don't stand
where the knife is coming.
All right, it's ready.
A hefty amount of salt.
So, we're gonna get it
in there.
Same thing
with the black pepper.
Nice, coarse ground.
Then we got some garlic.
Mexican oregano.
And we're roasting this
with the bone in.
Bone in.
I got some bay leaves.
We're gonna put
that achiote slurry.
So, we've got lemon juice,
orange juice,
and the achiote paste.
I just kind of pat it around,
get it in there.
So it doesn't knock
the crust off.
Right.
You're like
a "swine-estitician."
Beautiful, beautiful.
So, we're just gonna put
this banana leaf in there
to seal all the juices.
That's the plastic wrap
that they had?
Absolutely.
A little O.J.
A little sour orange.
Sour orange.
Naranja agria.
Let's do this.
Okay, so, into the oven.
How long?
6, 8, depends on your pork,
250, low and slow.
Oh, look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
Say hello
to my little pig.
Look at that.
A little crust there.
So, you can have it
with tacos or a torta.
Or in the "hand-a."
All right, we're gonna plate
this up.
You ready to eat it?
Look at that.
We're gonna get it
all nice and juicy.
See, the jus,
that's the kicker right there.
Topped with pickled onions.
Finish with pico de gallo.
That's ridiculous.
You see the little
dance kick there?
I don't know
where that came from.
Everything fires off.
You get all of the flavor
profiles,
from the sour to the sweet
to the salty, to the spicy.
Oh, my gosh, and then you get
hot and cold.
My mouth is having just
some complete meltdown.
Mmm.
So, in other words,
it's good?
It's ridiculous.
That's Mayan flavors
right there.
They're my flavors now.
[ Laughs ]
Yes!
I have had the last meal
on "Triple D" so many times,
but I got to tell you,
without a doubt,
that's one of the best.
Slow-roasted pork
just melts in your mouth.
Mmm.
You got to come down.
Phoenix is calling you.
Some of the best "Triple D"
joints in the world,
and now put Barrio
on the list.
FIERI: Up next...
Rub-a-dub duck.
...we're headed
to Toronto, Canada...
That's crazy.
...where these folks
are mixing up
some funky flavors
on the fast road to Flavortown.
Baked nice and sticky.
I'm here on Yonge Street,
which is what's considered
the longest street in the world,
and it divides Toronto, Canada,
by the east and the west.
I'm here to check out a joint
that's been here since 1939.
This is the Rosedale Diner.
All the food here
is really great.
Best fries, by far,
in the city, hands down.
WOMAN:
This is the bison burger.
It's absolutely delicious
and juicy.
You got to try the h-hummus.
Did you just roll that
with a "h-hummus?"
It's all about the h-hummus.
To have a Middle Eastern touch
like this
is very unusual for a diner.
FIERI:
Then again, Dubi and Esti Filar
aren't your typical
restaurant owners.
Did you just tell him to get
his elbows off the table?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
A husband-and-wife team
who cleaned up this former
greasy spoon back in 1981.
Dubi works with the cooks
to come up with killer dishes.
And, Esti, what do you do here
besides be the boss?
Tell him what to say
and what to do.
and what to do -- very nice.
In '09, they brought in Toronto
native Chris Grainger
to run the kitchen,
and he's cranking out dishes
with Dubi and Esti's
Israeli flair
right next to straight-up
Canadian classics.
GRAINGER:
Poutine au canard.
So, we're making
duck cheese fries.
Yeah, with gravy.
With gravy.
Yeah.
So, some fresh duck,
not been frozen.
We'll get the legs
and the thighs.
Yeah,
we've trimmed them up,
taken a bunch
of the fat off,
rendered that down.
Okay.
We're gonna start
with some salt,
some peppercorns.
Give it a Canadian kick
with some maple syrup.
Some pureed garlic,
fresh-picked rosemary,
some fresh-picked thyme.
Lastly, some bay leaves
before we mix this all up.
So, now you're just gonna get
in the tub with the duck?
Yeah, rub it up.
Rub-a-dub duck.
You got it.
Hit it.
All right,
we're gonna get in here
and make sure we show
every one of these guys
a little bit of love.
And how long is this gonna
sit here and set up?
We're gonna wrap this guy up
and throw it into the cooler
for about a full day.
Got it.
So, stovetop confit.
Stovetop duck confit.
We have our duck that's
marinated for a full day.
A bunch
of rendered duck fat,
and I mean a bunch
of rendered duck fat.
Get everybody in there.
There we go.
Okay, so, that sits there.
Let it go
for about two and a half hours.
Let it cool.
Then skin off,
shred the meat off the bone.
You got it.
Ready to go. Dig it.
Next up.
Next up, gravy.
Melt some butter down.
Add our duck fat in.
Add our flour
and make a quick roux.
Let this guy cook out
for a minute.
Cook "auwt."
Next up, our demiglace,
which we make in-house.
Veal bones and all?
That's right,
veal bones and all.
We also add a bit of chocolate,
red wine to it.
Add a little bit of
our chicken stock, which...
Of course, we make in-house.
Of course.
Now we're adding the duck
essence from our confit duck.
So, that's all of the gelatins
that come out of the duck,
out of the bone,
out of the joints?
Yeah, that's right.
Finish this guy with some salt,
a little black pepper.
We're gonna let this gravy
cook down for about an hour.
From this state?
From this state.
[ Whistles ]
Just to, you know,
concentrate all those flavors.
Okay, now we'll make
the fries.
We've got some nice
quarter-inch,
blanched Russet fries.
Yeah.
We have a special touch
to them.
We add sliced white onions.
We've been doing this
for 25 years.
It's Dubi's idea.
Okay, drop them.
All right.
How long do these take
to come up?
Three to four minutes.
Hit it with some salt.
Give a nice toss.
We're gonna plate this guy.
Mmm, that was a good fry.
I like that little
onion kick there.
Topped with some
Quebecois cheese curds.
Ooh,
No clue what that meant.
The real deal,
from Quebec.
So, now
that goes in the oven.
Come out, hit it with the duck,
then hit it with the gravy.
You got it.
Ohh.
Oh, my God.
Whew.
Wow.
That's crazy.
The duck
is unbelievably tender,
and the richness
of this canard --
French for "duck" --
gravy is outrageous.
Very decadent.
It's such a refined meal.
I mean, I say if it's funky,
I'll find it,
but this is fancy funky.
I mean, all I need to do
is have a little candle.
[ Romantic music plays ]
Maybe some white wine.
And could someone please
dim the lights.
That's what
I'm talking about.
Can you feel it?
Pure elegance.
Dig it.
A party in your mouth.
When you need comfort food,
that's what you go for.
That's what it is?
That's it.
FIERI: And when we come back,
Chris is doing up some ribs
a little bit different.
We're gonna boil
our ribs.
[ Whistles ]
Don't go away.
FIERI: We're north of the border
in Toronto, Canada,
at the Rosedale Diner
where Dubi and Esti Filar
have offered up
an eclectic menu since 1981.
We basically do
what we like doing.
FIERI: That's why, in a place
that leans Middle Eastern,
it's not a stretch to see them
stacking up Asian barbecue.
The Asian pork ribs.
You have to try
the sticky ribs.
FIERI: The only real surprise
is how Chris is cooking them.
We're gonna boil our ribs.
[ Whistles ]
You don't seem like
a rib boiler to me.
No?
No.
But I'm here to learn.
I want to see what you do.
We're gonna toss our ribs
in the pot.
So, baby back ribs.
Toss in some salt,
black peppercorns,
bay leaf, juniper berry,
and finally cinnamon sticks.
Top this guy off
with cold water.
How long are we gonna
let these simmer?
Just until the meat starts
tearing away from the bone --
I'd say two hours,
two and a half.
Okay.
Boiling a rib.
This cavalcade of ingredients
is going to create...
Our house-made hoisin.
Hoisin sauce?
You got it.
Really? Okay.
We're gonna add
soy sauce first,
a little bit of molasses,
some white vinegar.
All right.
Some maple syrup.
Hence the sticky.
You got it.
Very nice, eh?
Some tahini.
Yes, 'cause that's exactly
what I expected next.
O.J.
Good old orange juice.
A little bit of sriracha.
Okay.
Some brown sugar.
Word.
Put a bit of granulated garlic,
some pepper.
We're gonna whisk in
our sesame oil.
All right.
And then we're gonna
cook this down?
We're gonna cook this down.
How much will it reduce by,
half?
A little less than half,
until it's nice and sticky.
Put that on a --
I don't know.
Anything.
I like it.
So, the hoisin sauce
is cooking down.
It's starting to really smell
like hoisin sauce,
and the rib's in there
with the cinnamon
and the peppercorns
and the juniper berries.
It's ready to go?
It's ready to go.
Okay.
There we go.
We're gonna hack
these guys up.
And with that beautiful smoker
out there,
you don't smoke them?
You just --
This, you think, gets them
the right tenderness?
Trust me, Guy.
Hey, I trust you, man.
You're the one that made
duck gravy fries.
Tossing these guys
in a pan.
Okay.
So, you hit them
into a sauté pan,
hit them
with the hoisin sauce.
A little chicken stock
in there, yeah,
and get it reducing nice and hot
on the stovetop.
Toss them in the oven,
get them really baked,
nice and sticky,
pull them out.
Baked nice and sticky.
That's right.
That's like it should be a song
in the '80s.
♪ Baked ni-- ♪
You know what I mean.
Yeah.
Thank you.
All right.
Bring the ribs.
Oh, gorgeous.
Our ribs
are out of the oven.
They're nice and sticky.
We're gonna hit this with
some toasted sesame seeds.
Give them a nice toss.
We're ready to plate.
A rib castle for you.
Rib castle.
Yeah. Okay.
Make them pretty,
add some fries,
and our sticky Asian ribs.
Now they're gonna
fall over.
Oh, God,
the bone's hot!
Mmm,
the hoisin sauce is nice.
The meat's super-tender.
Anything that you lost
in boiling the rib,
you compensated for
in that hoisin sauce.
That stuff is sticky
and righteous.
Gosh, that's good.
Excellent job, Chef,
really nice job.
The meat is melting
in your mouth.
The sauce has that really
awesome twang to it.
It's amazing.
WOMAN:
They're just ooey-gooey good.
Awesome place.
In "Triple D," we say
if it's funky, we'll find it.
We found it north of the border.
Thanks for having me.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Dude, what are you doing?!
"Triple D" rules!
[ Laughter ]