Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Rattling ]
That was quiet.
That's the loudest thing
we do here.
...I'm taking my Vitamin C, mom,
'cause it's chicken, chili,
and chowder.
All right,
let's make this.
In Toronto, Canada,
the real-deal smokehouse...
Anything you don't want to
eat in your lifetime,
smear that on it.
...doing the funky chicken
right next to a burger
loaded with butter.
Brother,
that is the balance.
In Burbank, California...
He put his finger in it.
Did you see that?
...the old-school chili house.
You're gonna say
this is...
Number one.
...rocking a 65-year-old recipe.
I don't think I've had it
offered that way.
And in Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania...
the shot bar
turned gourmet hot spot
cooking up a chowder
with an Italian surprise.
Wow!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So I'm right between downtown
and midtown in Toronto, Canada,
in the Hillcrest Village area
of St. Clair Avenue West
to check out a joint that's
serving up the kind of food
you'd expect in these parts --
a smokehouse.
This is The Stockyards
Smokehouse & Larder.
One barbecued beef brisket.
The best barbecue I've ever had.
It's insane.
It's not your typical
Southern cuisine.
We need to drop fries
and the green tomatoes, please.
MAN: It's unique. It's Tom's
take on those flavors,
but he does it in his own way.
FIERI:
That would be the Tom Davis way
developed on the runway...
You're a runway model?
Back in the day.
...and tweaked
in his own kitchen.
Order up!
Two Butter Burgers!
DAVIS:
One of my dreams
was to open up my own
sort of smokehouse and diner.
I was smoking
in my backyard.
People just started digging
what I was doing.
In '09, he went from catering
to his own brick and smoker.
He puts his heart and soul into
everything that he does here.
Hot, hot, hot!
Everything on this menu
is brilliant.
Giant chunks of fried chicken
and griddle-cooked hamburgers
done right.
Butter Burger -- best burger
I've ever had in my entire life.
Out of all the burgers
you've had in your life?
It's sin on a bun.
We're gonna make
the Butter Burger.
Butter Burger.
With bone marrow?
With bone marrow.
These are
veal marrow bones.
So, line them up?
This is like chess
in Flavortown.
Put this into the oven
for about 45 minutes at 425.
Very cool.
So, these have
all cooked down,
and how are we gonna
get those out?
We're gonna use
a handy cocktail spoon.
They should come out
real easy.
That fatty,
delicious...
Fatty beauty.
So now that we've got all
the marrow out, next step?
Red-wine reduction,
unsalted butter,
our blue cheese.
And then we combine
all the ingredients together
till you start sweating.
The warm marrow
is melting everything.
Kind of help tying it
all together.
That is killer.
Anything you don't want to eat
in your lifetime,
smear that on it.
A good glob.
Roll it up
like a sausage,
and we put those
into the fridge to let them...
Congeal.
Congeal and harden.
So, special grind
with the hanger steak.
Six ounces.
Kosher salt
right on the griddle.
Custom-made
burger smasher.
Hold down for one second.
Helps create a nice,
beautiful crust on the burger.
Salt that.
About three minutes
per side.
Bun?
Our butter roller.
Put a nice browning
on the bun.
Shall we do the flip?
Do you see the juice?
The juice is loose.
Very nice.
Look at that
really nice crust on that.
Butter puck.
Nice.
Beautiful...
Nice toast.
...color on that.
Just put down
butter lettuce.
Whoa.
And then we top it off
with the fried onion.
Pardon me.
Yeah, please do.
The bun is just
soaking up the butter.
You may need
one of those.
That's the kind of napkin
you need
with a burger
like this.
It's so decadent.
It's got this smooth,
silky, velvety appeal
with these rich flavors,
and then, all of a sudden,
you get that crunch.
Crunch, right.
You get the crunch
and the texture.
Killer, man.
Great job.
Thanks, brother.
So I had to bring in
a real authority,
someone that is
from Toronto,
someone who's a chef, someone
who knows how to cook,
someone who's got
all that insight.
This is my friend Eden.
So, Eden, give me
the rundown here.
Mmm.
Just so buttery.
I love that blue cheese
because that blue cheese
gives it that tanginess
and that crust on the meat.
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
Everything you put in your mouth
here is good.
I mean, sandwiches --
some of them are meats
that Tom smokes here.
Another Bat Sandwich Combo.
I'm having the Bat sandwich
today.
FIERI: Tom's Southern-fried take
on the BLT.
WOMAN: Bacon, arugula,
and fried green tomatoes.
We're making
our bacon cure.
Kosher salt, brown sugar,
and our curing salt.
So we'll rub it down,
let it sit for 10 days.
FIERI:
Then it hits the smoker.
What in the...?
How many racks,
ribs at a time?
We can go about 60 racks
in there.
What temperature does
this hold really nice at?
We're cold smoking,
so we're about 100 degrees --
let this go
for 10, 12 hours.
Then we'll bring
the temperature up a touch.
Close 'er up.
Let's go.
Okay.
Okay, homey.
I love fried green tomatoes.
Give me the rundown.
Cornmeal.
Onion powder.
Paprika.
Cayenne.
Garlic powder.
Oregano. Sage.
Salt and pepper.
Okay.
In the flour.
Egg and buttermilk wash.
Over to the cornmeal.
Into the fryer.
And what temperature
are we gonna fry that at?
About 375.
Nice and crispy.
You got it.
And then it goes
together.
Yeah, this just came
out of the smoker.
Okay, so this is how thick
you make this.
How many planks of this
are they getting?
Two on the Bat.
All right, let's make this.
So we only toast this bread
on one side.
Okay, so you don't
just kill the top of your mouth
on the other side.
That's right.
That is
our lemon crème fraiche.
Arugula.
Lay down our two strips
of Stockyards' thick-cut bacon.
Dude, that's ridiculously
thick-cut.
Topped
with fried green tomato.
And now...
Take your time.
Mm.
I had to get a big bite
out of that.
The herbaceous side
of the arugula,
a little bit of that acid coming
through from the crème fraiche,
the salt, the crunch of
the coating of the green tomato,
the richness
or a little bit of that smoke --
That real deep undertone
coming through from that bacon
makes this just
an unbelievable sandwich.
Brother,
that is the balance.
So, speaking of what
a great sandwich that is,
the only chance I'm gonna
give you to beat that is
with the fried chicken.
So when we come back, we're
hanging out at the Stockyard,
and this man Tom
is off the hook.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Seriously, brother.
Thank you, brother.
[ Sizzling ]
All right,
so "Triple D" is back,
and we've gone
international.
We're in Toronto, Canada,
in the Hillcrest Village area
at The Stockyards,
and what are we gonna make now?
Stockyards' fried chicken.
And I hear it's the bomb.
The fried chicken is the best
you'll ever have in your life.
MAN;
It is just juicy and crispy
and all delicious
all at the same time.
It's beautiful.
So we've broken it down
to 10 pieces. Next step?
We have to make our brine.
Salt and sugar.
A little bit of warm water.
Bay leaf.
Okay.
Fresh thyme.
Whole garlic cloves.
Dig it.
Allspice.
Whole peppercorns.
And red onion.
Fill that
with ice-cold water.
I like the direction
this is all going.
And we'll just fill
that baby up.
Bobbing for chicken,
huh?
[ Laughs ]
So into the fridge,
24 hours.
Next step is a marinade.
Cayenne.
Paprika.
Lemon pepper.
Nice touch.
Kosher salt.
And ground pepper.
Mix in
our lovely buttermilk.
It's combined nicely.
You see the nice little color
in that.
We'll take drum,
half a breast.
Get yourself a thigh, son.
There we go.
Wing.
Okay.
So, that comes together.
Tie that baby up.
Goes back into the walk-in
for 24 hours.
The marinated chicken is going
into the seasoned flour.
What temp in the fryer?
About 315.
315?
Yes.
And what are we frying in --
what kind of oil?
Canola oil.
How long
does this batch go?
13.
And you know when it's done
'cause it's gonna start dancing.
It's gonna start dancing?
The chicken dances
in the fryer.
Oh.
That's the one
right there.
Finish it
with some fries...
and some
of our Thai bird chili hot sauce
and house-made coleslaw.
I'm a wing man.
Mmm.
But look at that chicken.
All the things
that fried chicken should be.
Seasoned a little bit,
but balanced.
You get the notes of the pepper
and the salt and the hot.
That's how barbecue sauce
is supposed to go with chicken.
It's not
super-over-the-top hot
that's gonna burn
your palate out.
If you don't come and
try it with the hot sauce,
you're missing it.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Awesome, man.
This beats mama's fried chicken.
[ Laughs ]
Forgive me.
I love this place.
Absolutely.
The Stockyard really does
something special for my soul.
This is as good as it gets.
You ain't gonna get better.
You get it
from Larry himself.
FIERI: Every time we come
up to Canada, we find
really great food,
but this, man,
you'd be hard-pressed
to tell me
you weren't coming
from North Carolina.
Oh, that's a compliment.
Well done.
Thank you.
Brothers hug.
FIERI: Coming up...
We're headed west to Burbank,
California...
So here
at the chili dome...
...for a decades-old
institution...
I'm like Bubba
and Forrest Gump
are having a talk
right now on the bus.
...giving a class on chili.
[ Imitating Bubba ]
Chili and spaghetti,
chili and beans...
So I'm here in Burbank,
California.
Now, when most people think
about Southern California,
they think great weather,
dynamite Mexican food,
and health food,
but do they think
like old-school chili joints
from 1946?
Well, they will
after they visit this place.
This is Chili John's.
It kind of feels like
a 1950's diner.
[ Cash register dings ]
This is like a "Happy Days,"
you know.
This is so old school,
the recipe for the chili
came with the building
when Debra LoGuercio
and her husband
bought the joint
more than two decades ago.
Now her sons Anthony and Alec
are serving up the same recipe.
We're an old-school
Italian family,
and this chili has garlic in it,
so we can cook it.
If it has garlic in it,
you got license to do it.
And they took that license
to start dishing out some
of their own chili recipe.
We have chili dogs.
Chicken chili.
Veggie chili.
Vegetarian chili.
I'm like Bubba
and Forrest Gump
are having a talk
right now on the bus.
[ Imitating Bubba ]
Chili and spaghetti,
chili and beans,
chili and tamale.
[ Laughs ]
But the staple around here
is the original
Texas-style beef chili.
So we're gonna start
our beef chili.
Pot's hot.
We're gonna take
our ground-beef suet.
So the suet,
this is the beef fat.
Best you can buy.
All right,
so we cook this down.
This will take
about 45 minutes.
Got it.
And then we will render out
the cracklings.
Here's our cracklings.
So this is the little bit
of meat that was in the suet.
This is going to go
into our grinder.
We're gonna grind this down
with our garlic.
So we have the hot tub
of liquid fat.
What kind of beef?
This is just
peeled beef knuckle.
Okay.
So we'll stir this
for a good four hours
before we're ready to add
any of our spices.
So when we know it's ready,
we're gonna do the smush test.
Ah, the smush test.
If it mushes,
it's almost cooked down
to where it melts in your mouth.
Yes.
Ready for the spices.
We'll start with cumin.
Oregano. Thyme.
Our salt.
Remember those cracklings?
With the garlic.
There's a lot of flavor
in the cracklings.
Now we stir.
This will sit
for half an hour,
and then we'll add
our chili-powder blend.
But eating that...
Whoo.
Dummy put his finger in it!
Did you see that?
This has to stir
for half an hour.
The final spice --
hot cayenne.
Let this go
for another half an hour,
and then we put it
on the steam table.
Okay.
I love it, man.
So here at the chili dome,
how can I have it?
However you want.
Some beans...
Some spaghetti...
Some hot chili...
Some cheddar cheese...
Some onions.
I have done it up with the
majority of the ingredients.
Mmm.
Yeah, there's nothing like
that extra suet.
I don't think I've had it
offered that way.
Nope.
Nobody makes it like this.
Mmm. Not too spicy.
I like the mixture of the beans
to the spaghetti.
Nicely done, my friend.
I can't keep shoving it
in my mouth fast enough.
It's spiced perfectly.
It's good, man.
It's the best chili
I've had in California.
Well, 65 years
speaks pretty well for it.
I don't think we have to
really get into much
more detail, do we?
You can tell it's all homemade
with heart and love.
FIERI: Have you guys changed
any of the recipes?
ALEC: Only addition, no changes,
no subtractions.
Out of all the chili joints
you've got in California,
you're gonna say this is...
Number one.
This is the place that you will
kick yourself, Burbank,
that you've been driving by
for this many years
and you've never
tried it.
You got to come check it out.
Thanks for having me.
FIERI: Up next,
We're Philly bound...
This is awesome.
...for a scrappy
neighborhood joint...
I like this method.
...making my kind of chowder.
Clam chowder
and gnocchi?
I'm here at a great "Triple D"
town -- Philadelphia --
in southwest Center City --
to check out a joint
that for 60 years was
just a shot-and-beer place.
Now it's three stories
of upscale bar food.
This is Sidecar.
And that's also a sidecar.
Pork nachos up!
It's a neighborhood joint.
And the food is fantastic.
Some of the best
that I've ever tasted.
You just feel like you're
a part of something.
[ Engine turns over ]
FIERI: Yep, part of
Adam Ritter's midlife crisis.
I was working in sales.
I was selling forklifts
and warehouse designs.
I wanted to become a chef.
I wanted to open up
something like this.
Whoo!
So he cut to the chase
and picked up this property
in 2005.
Next think I know, my wife and I
own a shot-and-beer bar.
So you weren't even
in culinary school yet?
No.
That's when he leaned
on Brian Lofink,
a local
who is a culinary grad.
MAN: It's an incredibly
original menu.
Everything that they
come up with is a twist
on something that I know.
But don't be expecting
your mama's burger...
Piggy burger up!
...or your granny's
clam chowder.
WOMAN: They actually have
potato gnocchi in there,
and it's so heavenly good.
Oh, to die for.
[ Laughs ]
Clam chowder and gnocchi?
Yep.
It's our little spin
on a clam chowder.
Let's roll.
Hot potato?
Hot potatoes.
We're going to cut these
in half.
You got to do it right away.
Otherwise, the potatoes
get real gummy, and it makes
a really poor product.
I take it we're gonna just kind
of rice them through this?
Take it right here,
pop them right out.
Now with this spoon,
we push them right through.
I like the method, man.
Yeah, it works out
pretty good.
And at this point, what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna season it
with freshly ground
black pepper.
Some salt. Butter.
Some extra-virgin olive oil.
There we go.
I'm gonna crack two eggs
in here.
Going pretty rustic
on this one.
It's what we do.
Little chive.
This is awesome.
Then we're gonna mix
all this up together.
Okay.
All with a bench knife.
That's it.
Everything's all mixed together
and happy now.
Then we add in our flour.
We're just gonna cover the top
of it here.
We don't mix it all together
'cause it creates
too much gluten.
We're gonna cut this baby
in half,
and we're just gonna keep
folding over top,
pressing it
and pressing it.
Kind of almost
in the biscuit theory.
Exactly.
I don't think I've ever done
the cut and stack.
This has got to be some nice
and light gnocchi, huh?
Yeah, it pretty much
just melts in your mouth.
I like this method.
So after we get it
all mixed together,
we're gonna let it sit
for about a half-hour.
It had a chance to rest,
so we take this off.
We just dust this
with a little bit of flour.
Cut a little edge off
like that.
Okay.
We roll it out nice and light.
We be gentle with it.
Then we just kind of come
to the edge here and cut down.
Yeah.
Sprinkle some bench flour
over top of it.
So they don't dry out.
Scoop them up.
Just toss it up.
Beautiful.
All right, so now we're gonna go
and make the clam stock?
We're gonna take our clams --
littleneck clams, by the way.
[ Rattling ]
That was quiet.
That's the loudest thing
we do here.
We're gonna take our onions,
add them in.
Carrots. Celery.
So the mirepoix.
Little bit of garlic.
Fresh thyme.
Fresh parsley.
Bay leaf.
Whole black peppercorns.
We just cover this
with water.
This will also make
the broth.
Yep.
Cover this with foil.
Fire it up,
let them go 10 minutes.
You'll strain it.
These are the cool clams
that we're gonna pick
for our clam chowder.
We're gonna assemble the whole
clam chowder right here.
So we got
applewood-smoked bacon here.
We're gonna get it
nice and crisp.
Add in our shallot, garlic.
Get our light toast on this.
Add in our clams.
Clam stock.
We drop our gnocchi.
These gnocchis are rising,
so we're gonna add these
to our pan.
The starches
from these gnocchi
is gonna help thicken
the sauce.
Now a little cream.
Mount it
with a little butter.
Season with
a little bit of salt,
a little bit
of black pepper.
Tighten it up.
And we're ready to plate.
That's ridiculous.
Take some
of our crispy shallots here.
Oh!
Shove them in my face.
[ Laughs ]
And we finish it with
a little celery-leaf salad.
Very nice.
The gnocchi's delicate --
depth and flavor,
and you get a little bit
of the clam and the creaminess.
But it's not the creaminess
in the sauce,
it's the creaminess
in the gnocchi itself.
Mmm.
And then the salad on it.
[ Sighs ]
The salad on the top
is what makes it. Wow!
This is literally one
of the best gnocchi
dishes I've ever had.
Oh, awesome, man.
Amazing.
Clam chowder up!
The gnocchis are so light
and fluffy.
The salt and the cream ratio
is like just right.
And that little celery salad
on top?
Very nice.
Forget about it.
Ohh.
It's excellent.
It's ridiculous.
Real food.
Nothing pretentious.
Inventive and interesting.
Congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
I'm telling you.
You won it.
You got Jenny,
you got the sidecar,
and then you named
the joint.
The big winner, huh?
Chicken dinner.
Winner, winner, chicken dinner.
Watch out for this guy.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip.
But don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
That butter is in -- Oh.
[ Laughs ]
He's watching out for me.
No, you have some --
There you go.
Okay,
you're almost good.
Thanks, Guy.
Yeah, I'm here for you.
What would I do
without you?
Just go for another bite.