Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hello, Flavortown?
Yeah, my pig meter's going off.
...it's traditional gone wild...
That's a new one.
...on Philadelphia's south side.
I'm out of breath.
A taproom
taking over the town...
Peanut butter and jelly
going to table five.
FIERI: ...with surprises
on the plate...
Wow!
Oh, yeah.
This is it.
...and in the kitchen.
Whoo!
[ Sighs ]
Look at the time!
In Phoenix, Arizona...
That's it!
We're here!
...the fireside joint...
This guy's like a ninja.
...heating up
a big-time dip sandwich...
Now we're gonna take
this bad boy for a test drive.
...a one-of-a-kind pancake...
O-M-G.
...and their take
on a spicy meatball.
Everything
is touchdown bombs.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
"Triple D" is here
in South Philly
to go to this funky
little taproom you're
just gonna love --
Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
I said
you could drive the car.
This isn't "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives Unwrapped."
I'm Guy Fieri,
this is Marc Summers,
and we're here to check out
the South Philadelphia Tap Room.
Come on.
Check it out.
Unbelievable.
Just knock their socks off.
Vegan hoagie going to 21.
[ Bell dings ]
This bar
is the neighborhood.
We always knew that we were
gonna put something here
that probably didn't belong
in this neighborhood.
FIERI: There's a marketing plan
for you.
But if you build it,
they will come,
and they have.
This bar really had
a vital role
in revitalizing
this neighborhood.
And that gamble's
been paying of big time
for John Longacre since 2003.
This is, like,
where it's at?
It really is.
I mean, this is
as South Philly as it gets.
Those props
go to Chef Scott Schroeder.
Scott is fearless
in the kitchen.
MAN:
It's a little challenging,
and it pushed the boundaries
of your own taste buds.
It's normal to see things like
a fried peanut butter and jelly?
Normal for here.
You know Marc Summers.
I do.
Extraordinaire.
Since "Double Dare."
Oh, my.
You know what?
Marc lives here in Philly.
I thought he would be
the perfect guy to bring down
to South Philadelphia
to try the Tap Room.
So, Chef Scott,
what are you gonna make us?
My signature dish,
a fried peanut butter
and jelly sandwich.
So, we're gonna start
with making
the french toast batter.
We have eggs,
fresh-ground nutmeg,
salt, black pepper.
Really?
Vanilla extract, cinnamon.
Just whisk that in
a little bit.
Some sugar.
Heavy cream.
Some whole milk.
Okay.
Peanut butter and jelly.
White bread.
This is from Baker Street,
a local bakery
out in Chestnut Hill.
Peanut butter...
and then
strawberry preserves.
Okay.
PB&J's made.
Yeah.
So, now we're gonna just dip it
in the french toast batter.
What is this concoction here
of dust?
Ground Frosted Flakes,
just pulsed in a food processor.
Yeah, just on both sides,
nice and crusted
[ Laughing ] Oh, man.
Right?
How bad can that be?
Well, you get this
and you get a free Spanx shirt.
[ Laughter ]
Look at the cup of butter
that he put in there.
And the trick is
don't touch it at first.
The sugar
and the Frosted Flakes
are gonna
kind of caramelize.
So, how long on that side
are you frying it?
Two to three minutes.
Split it into fours.
Bon appétit.
You go first.
Oh, my.
Mmm.
[ Mumbling ]
Wow. That's awesome.
It's light.
It's not super heavy.
A really good jam,
nice creamy peanut butter.
Everybody loves a PB&J.
Take something simple,
push it up another level.
Outrageous.
What do you think, huh?
The cornflake topping...
[ Laughs ]
...is the pièce de résistance.
Frosted flakes --
Cornflakes would
almost make it healthy.
Do we look like
we're on some health tour?
Look at us.
Come on!
Let's go chug some doughnuts!
MAN:
It's like being a kid again.
The twist on it
is the Frosted Flakes.
It just adds, like,
a texture and a crunch to it.
We bought the house because
this bar was across the street.
I won't lie.
[ Chuckles ]
WOMAN: I'm a really big fan
of craft beer,
and there's always
something new to try.
The ricotta doughnuts
are so good.
FIERI: Sure, everyone knows
a beerhouse is a great place
to get doughnuts.
Ricotta apple doughnuts
with hard cider caramel sauce.
All right, we're gonna start
by making the cider caramel.
This is hard cider.
And we're gonna reduce it
by how much?
Half.
So now we're gonna add
light brown sugar.
You got to add
some fat to it.
Add some butter...
and some heavy cream.
Then that's gonna cook down
for a little bit.
A little pinch of salt.
We're just gonna finish it
with a little bit more
of the raw cider.
Just to add that little --
Yeah, to give it
a little wake up.
Mmm. Oh, yeah.
That's tasty.
Be careful.
You've built
a monster, now.
Oh, yes!
That's fantastic!
Please, let's make these
before he drinks
any more of the cider.
[ Laughter ]
And ricotta?
Fresh ricotta cheese.
Sugar.
So, we're creaming it
and...
Now we're gonna add eggs.
So,
a little baking powder...
and a little bit
of vanilla extract.
Now we're gonna hit
with...
Now we're gonna add
some flour.
And we're just gonna
fold it in.
So, once that's
just incorporated,
we're gonna add some apples
that were just sautéed
in a little butter
and brown sugar.
Granny Smiths?
We're actually using
a local heirloom apple.
We're gonna go
into a fryer now.
So, they go into this mixture
of garam masala and sugar.
This just took
an Indian spin on us?
An Indian spin.
Garam masala is a mixture
of coriander and turmeric,
allspice, and fenugreek.
Cardamom
is a big aspect of it.
And then a little bit
of that caramel we made.
It's not a shot glass,
Summers.
[ Laughter ]
Nice and light.
A little bit of apple.
Wow!
Oh, yeah!
This is it!
I mean, this is big flavor,
uniquely made, great textures.
I mean,
just quality ingredients.
Can I say something?
Please go ahead.
I think we've just taken
a trip to Flavortown.
[ Laughs ]
Let him drive your car
one time.
WOMAN: They're, like, sweet,
savory, everything combined.
It wakes up your whole mouth.
All right, so,
we got to take a small break.
I'm hanging out
with my good buddy Marc Summers
and Chef Scott here at the
South Philadelphia Tap Room.
Now, when we get back,
you got anything else for us?
A house specialty that's head
and shoulders above the rest.
Head and shoulders
above the rest?
We'll see you
in a little bit.
All right,
so, here's "Triple D"
back at the Tap Room
in South Philly,
hanging out with my good friend
Marc Summers
and, of course, Chef Scott.
Now, you said
before we went to break
you had something special.
One of our biggest,
most popular-selling dishes,
unique, locally sourced,
handmade.
Mmm! What do you got for us,
Chef Scott?
Headcheese.
Whoo!
[ Sighs ]
Look at the time!
Is this --
No, that's not the way out.
Um...
oh, my God.
Okay! Uh, thanks
for inviting me!
Oh, yeah!
All right. I'm going to get
some oral surgery right now.
That sounds much better.
[ Laughs ]
Give us a rundown.
Sure.
We usually start
with brining it.
Boiling water.
Add some salt, sugar.
Dissolving the sugar --
Make sure
it's completely dissipated.
And then we're gonna add
the ice water.
And this
will just temper it.
So, that just goes in,
submerged.
24 hours in the walk-in.
Because we got a lot of bone,
we got a lot of
connective tissue.
It's gonna take awhile
to work it in there.
Yeah.
And then where are we going
with that?
Into a pot.
Cover it with water.
Onions, garlic,
peppercorns,
a little bay leaf,
and white vinegar.
Boil it down just till
it's becoming tender?
Yeah, just till
it's starting to pull apart.
Wish me luck.
Here in Flavortown,
it's bobbin' for pig heads!
There's a lucky winner.
So, there it is.
There we go.
So, every little bit
from the tongue to the snout.
Jowl here.
We have some cheek meat there.
That's my favorite.
To start with, the ears,
since they're crunchy,
we slice those
really thin.
The jowl meat,
just sort of hunk up.
That thick?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It's real luscious.
It'll melt on your tongue.
It's tongue
will melt on your tongue.
[ Laughs ]
And then we have
the reduced juice.
Oh, when that chills up,
that is just a --
Jell-O.
Yeah, that's pig Jell-O.
Little shake, make sure
you don't have any air pockets.
There you go.
So, we'll go
into the fridge with that.
24 hours -- Let it set up.
Only if Summers
was here to see it.
We cut it into logs,
and then we just do
some slices.
We have
fresh corn tortillas.
Headcheese
goes right on top.
A little fresh avocado,
queso fresco.
House pickled jalapeños
with some little mustard seed.
95 items on this.
Minced red onion.
Fresh cilantro.
A lime wedge.
And then a little bit
of the homemade hot sauce.
I'm out of breath.
Can I put a little bit
of the salsa right on it?
I recommend it.
Whoo!
I think just got a bit
of a little earlobe
or something like that.
[ Laughs ]
The textures are great.
The flavors are great.
All the supporting
cast members
in this orchestra of pig head
is outrageous.
Here's to you,
Marc Summers.
[ Laughs ]
You missed it!
It was a taste adventure.
Cassie, pick up --
Table 20.
Once people find out it's here,
they just keep coming in.
That just comes with being
a great restaurant.
WOMAN: I think everybody
who misses a night here
and goes some place else
in Philadelphia is
missing out on the best.
Well, listen, it's
a funky joint, nice people,
and you've got a real boss thing
there with Chef.
I mean,
he is a true talent.
This is a place
people got to check out.
Thank you.
Thanks for having me.
Thanks a million.
Appreciate it.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
to Phoenix, Arizona...
Really?
And that's how it works?
...where a fire-loving chef...
And it's awesome.
...is raising the roof
on the French-dip standard.
That's
pushing the boundaries.
I'm here in North Central
Phoenix, Arizona,
on Camelback Road
to check out a joint
that looks like it came from my
home turf -- the wine country --
and to meet a chef that's doing
my kind of cooking --
wood-fired.
This is St. Francis.
French onion burger up.
The food is fantastic always.
CHAMBERLIN:
Vegetable flatbread up.
Consistent good food.
It has, like, its own
unique little twists
and quirks and flavors.
FIERI: Just like the chef behind
it all -- Aaron Chamberlin.
I grew up as a Boy Scout.
I always cooked
on an open fire.
So, when he opened this joint
in '09,
he saw no reason
to do anything different.
I wanted to have
a big wood-burning oven
so I could have my little fire
going in my restaurant.
MAN: They're all masters
at what they do.
There's a lot of good stuff
on the menu.
FIERI:
Including this top seller.
Pig dip up.
Just like a French dip,
but pork style.
First thing we're gonna make
is our brine for our pork.
Water goes in.
So, bringing that up.
Second thing, star anise.
Very strong.
Fennel seed.
Bay leaf.
Toasted coriander seed.
Of course you toasted it.
Ancho chili.
We go on to
the fresh ingredients.
We got thyme there
and fresh rosemary.
Kosher salt.
You got the sugar.
Boom.
Bring this up to boil,
and we let it sit and marinate.
We have our brine,
just off the stove.
We strained all the spices
and herbs out of there.
I have some ice that I...
Oh, that's nice!
...slightly cooled down.
It's a good brine.
Mm! That star anise
is what really --
Comes through.
Yeah.
Mmm!
And we stick our pork
right in there.
Overnight -- 12 hours.
Overnight.
We put salt and pepper
on it...
and roast it
in the wood oven.
What temp
does the oven run?
The oven right now
is at 616 degrees.
Our roast is ready,
and you can see how nice
and beautiful it is.
I just come right in here.
Oh. That rack of ribs.
Yeah, you can smell that guy
right there.
Are you talking
about this guy, or...
Well, no, the pork.
Okay.
So, we have the chine
right there,
and then what we do
is we just slice nice,
little, thin pieces.
Layer our sandwich here.
Put applewood smoked bacon,
Gruyère cheese like that.
Back in the oven?
Back in the oven.
Let that melt.
We're gonna assemble
the sandwich.
Fennel-onion marmalade,
a generous amount of it.
Dijon mustard
for a little picante.
Melted cheese.
Just slide this
right off...
Oh, gosh.
...onto that.
We add prosciutto -- That's one
thing we don't cook --
and the top bun.
O-M-G.
Cut this in half.
We have our nice,
beautiful pork au jus.
Pig jus.
Put that right there.
Hello, Flavortown?
Yeah, my pig meter's going off.
Smoky, crunchy, creamy.
I haven't even dipped
this thing yet.
Now we're gonna take
this bad boy for a test drive.
That's it!
We've hit the destination!
We're here!
That's got to be
within the top five
best pork sandwiches
I've ever had,
combining that
with the top five
best dip sandwiches
I've ever had.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
WOMAN: It's delicious.
Nice, salty flavor.
The sauce
is really good.
The bread is crunchy,
but not soggy.
All the perfect things
about a sandwich.
Ohh.
One of the best dips
I've ever had.
This place definitely
stands out within Phoenix.
They're famous here
for their oven.
FIERI:
Which is cranking 24/7.
Well, at dinner, we actually
cook half chickens in it,
green chilli stew.
We do flatbreads.
And at the end of dinner,
bakers come in,
they make their bread.
And when morning
rolls around...
We make our pancake
right in the wood oven.
The iron skillet
olive oil pancake...
It's amazing.
First we're gonna start with
the basic pancake batter --
all-purpose flour...
baking powder,
baking soda, salt...
sugar.
FIERI: Okay.
Mix all the dry there.
So, for
the wet ingredients,
I have my buttermilk,
eggs.
[ Whistles ]
Good amount of buttermilk.
Then we put it right
in the middle of the well.
Thank you.
Next ingredient, we actually
add extra virgin olive oil.
Pancake batter done.
Next thing we're gonna make
is the caramel apples.
Smokin' hot pan out
of the oven.
We're gonna add butter.
It's gonna go quick, though.
Yes, it is.
Apples.
Apples in.
Sugar.
A little bit of vanilla paste.
Come on, little guy.
Vanilla paste --
Do you make this vanilla paste?
We don't. We buy it.
It's the new rage,
and it's awesome.
Well, I'm gonna go ahead
and make the pancake.
A lot of extra virgin
olive oil.
You got to put a little crust
on this.
We want to, like,
shallow fry it
so it gets nice
and golden brown.
So, this is actually
a dangerous one...
'Cause as we --
It's bubbling over, sir.
Captain.
It's all right.
It's all good.
Your Honor, Your Honor.
In.
Really?
And that's how it works?
You're gonna see it
start puffing up,
and then the fire's gonna
golden it -- We turn it.
Starting to pull up, while
our apples are sizzle-sizzling.
This guy's like a ninja.
This is
an iron skillet pancake.
One of the things
with the iron skillet pancake,
is we want it to have
a little char on it.
We don't want it to be
real blond.
Apples are
getting ready.
A little
apple napalm, huh?
Nice and crunchy.
That's nuts.
Here we have
the carameled apples.
Put these
right over the top.
A little bit
of maple syrup.
Whipped
crème fraîche.
Extra virgin olive oil
on top.
Cooking pancakes
when I was a kid
was done
in a cast-iron skillet.
We'd pack up
for the mountains on horses.
My dad always
used to sell me
on the idea that
when it had a little char,
it's 'cause it was rustic
and it was campfire cooking.
Yeah.
There you go.
Look at that.
Wow.
The apples are tender.
The cake is moist.
It's got a little bit
of that char,
which adds to it
so it's not so sweet.
Wow! That's pushing
the boundaries.
It's outrageous.
Iron skillet pancake up.
WOMAN:
It was an emotional experience
for me when I first had it.
It brought tears to my eyes
it was so good.
I don't know if I can do
one more dish.
You guys in?
They're in.
You in?
I'm in.
Don't go anywhere.
We're hanging out at St. Francis
in Phoenix, Arizona,
with Chef Aaron.
Dude's off the hook.
See you in a bit.
FIERI: "Triple D" is camped out
at St. Francis
in Phoenix, Arizona,
where Chef Aaron Chamberlin
is combining handcrafted food...
CHAMBERLIN:
Green chili soup coming up.
...with a fiery inferno
for some dynamite results.
Wood-fired
baked eggs up.
Here, even the meatballs
get kissed by the flames.
So, what are we
on to, brother?
Moroccan-inspired
meatballs.
We have our
house-made bread.
Okay.
We take water
and we soak the bread.
Ground beef.
Okay.
Ground fresh,
made in-house.
You grind in-house?
We do.
Our fresh ground pork.
Garlic and shallots,
sweated down.
Sweated down.
Ground ginger,
cumin...
chili powder,
smoked paprika.
Salt.
Some salt.
Cilantro.
Parsley.
Got it.
A little bit
of fresh pepper.
Eggs right in.
That's our binder, and then
we'll squeeze the breadcrumbs.
Great looking bread, man.
Okay.
You know the drill.
We don't want to mix
too much.
I don't mind seeing a little
chunk of bread here and there.
A little rustic.
Then we take a scoop.
Scoop it out.
In the walk-in,
we let it chill.
Sear them
on the stovetop.
All right, so, the meatballs
are done now.
Now we're gonna make
our sauce.
This is what really takes it
to the Moroccan.
It does. We have right here
our house-made tomato sauce.
So, the first thing we add to it
is our harissa.
More smoked paprika...
ground cinnamon...
and our cumin,
toasted and ground.
Cilantro.
We mix.
That's Moroccan.
Okay, so, I'm gonna ladle
these over right now.
They're gonna just kind of
soak up that sauce and heat up.
There you go.
Love it.
We're plating up
the Moroccan meatballs,
so we have this
Israel couscous
we put in the bottom
of the pan.
Then we get
our meatballs.
Two, three.
Meatball sauce.
Nice!
Right there.
And then we have
a cheese blend,
mixture of a couple different
mozzarellas and a cheddar,
and in the oven.
We're basically just heating up,
making golden bubbly brown.
So, it takes
about seven minutes.
"We're making
golden bubbly brown."
Yep.
And then we garnish it with
a little bit of lime juice
right over the top
of the meat.
A little extra virgin
olive oil.
Shine them up.
Some cilantro.
And then a little slice
of our toasted homemade bread.
Wow.
There's no doubt
that's Moroccan.
Yeah.
You get that harissa
right off the bat.
That spice.
The meatball itself
is very rich.
Good amount of bread.
Good texture to it.
Not heavy.
It's got
the right balance.
Great job.
Thank you.
Meatballs up.
It's just amazing.
This is like a vacation,
and it's just down
the street from us.
You don't play
anything safe.
Everything
is touchdown bombs.
I've had
an incredible visit.
Thank you.
You got to come
meet this cat. Amazing.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more
"Triple D" joints
all over the country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives."
When did you have
a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich last, Summers?
Uh...several years ago.
I can't think of the last time
I had one.
What, the one
Betsy Ross made you?
[ Laughing ]
That's exactly right.
We went down
before we made the flag.
[ Laughs ]