Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Camera's not on, is it?
I'm getting in the ring...
Let's roll.
...with some serious
Flavortown champs.
This is like an extra week now
at the gym.
Round 1...
Phoenix, Arizona.
What?
A one-two combo of comfort food
and wicked workouts.
It's like culinary Christmas.
Round 2...
Okay, hit it.
...Leucadia, California.
The beach-town taco shack...
I can see your saliva
right now.
...putting wicked moves...
Everything's in balance.
...on the traditional taco.
All-American Dream.
Word!
And in Mount Airy,
Pennsylvania...
the knockout punch...
This is a new one for me.
...of sensational
southern cooking.
I'm so happy you like it.
Oh, I am so happy
you made it.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
I'm down here
in Phoenix, Arizona.
I love coming down here.
The weather --
I mean, those warm nights,
sitting outside,
listening to great tunes,
eating great food,
hanging out with your friends.
I mean, I wish someone
could make a restaurant concept
around that.
Oh, yeah, they did.
This is The Duce.
Pot pie.
Slick Willy, come on up.
Enjoy, buddy.
There's nothing like it
in Phoenix.
[ Record scratches ]
Is this normal in Phoenix?
This is a great place
to hang out. Look at it.
I mean,
you have everything --
shopping, boxing, food, bar.
Shopping, boxing,
food, and bar.
FIERI: All things
Windy City transplants
Steve and Andi Rosenstein love.
It's almost like
our personal playground.
So what did you guys do
in Chicago?
We had a clothing company
that we started
right out of college.
We sold the business
in 2006.
FIERI:
Before heading to Phoenix,
setting up shop in a warehouse
area called The Duce.
Here Steve whips them in shape
while Andi runs the kitchen --
a.k.a. an airstream trailer --
and cranks out
her family favorites...
Order up. Pot pie.
...which are
very, very unique.
We're baking in this?
We're baking in that.
This I got to see.
We're gonna start
by making the dough.
Flour, a little kosher salt,
a little bit of sugar.
And we're gonna cut in
our butter.
Wow.
Pulse that in.
Okay.
Get in there.
Form it into a big ball.
Let this rest?
And let it rest.
Flatten it out a little bit
so it's easier to roll.
Okay, good to go.
And we use the tops of our
mason jars to cut a circle.
Build the bottom,
form the sides,
and then I've got to cut
the tops out.
Here we go.
And you power-bake them.
These go in the oven
what temp?
You pop in the oven at 350,
two, three minutes.
We're gonna get
in the filling?
We're gonna make
the filling.
Start with butter.
You feel that it's okay
to give copious amounts
of butter in your food
because you have
a boxing ring?
I fatten them up.
Steve trims them down.
We're gonna add
boneless chicken thigh.
Get so fly
with the chicken thigh?
It doesn't dry out as much
as white meat does.
We tried it
with white meat.
I'm gonna brown that.
We're gonna add in a little
chopped onion,
add diced celery,
and a little carrot,
a little kosher salt.
We're gonna add
a little chicken stock,
and we're gonna
let that simmer.
So while that's browning,
we're gonna make the roux.
We're going to start
with a little butter.
Whisk in a little flour
Let that thicken
a little bit.
Okay, you want
the chicken stock.
Heavy cream.
Stir that till it thickens.
So the roux goes in
with the chicken,
and now the corn,
so it stays nice and tender.
Parsley.
We'll let it continue
to tighten up.
Okay, so,
we have these baked off.
Now you're gonna fill them.
All the way to the top.
That's a nice little portion
you're giving in there.
We're gonna top it with
the circle of pie dough.
And then we're gonna pop them
in the oven.
And they're ready to taste.
Smoking hot.
Mmm!
Really nice flaky crust.
And the key is that corn.
Fresh corn.
But the kicker --
chicken thigh makes it.
Yeah.
That dark meat
is still tender.
Great flavor.
There's a little bit of crust
on the side.
Ohh!
There you go.
Come to Papa.
Mmm!
Nice job!
All right.
MAN: It's amazing.
I mean, it's loaded with
vegetables, which is awesome.
It's almost like a cookie.
It's got a little sweetness
to it, but it is just delicious.
Good job, you got the gym
right next door.
I plan on working out
after I eat.
[ Bell rings ]
FIERI: Have you guys
been in the ring?
Yes.
I boxed my brother two days
before his wedding in that ring
'cause his rehearsal dinner
was here.
Seriously?
And what is your favorite
menu item?
The mac and cheese bites.
These are good.
Mac and cheese muffins.
ANDI:
Two of my favorite words.
Butter?
Butter!
Flour.
Add in the milk.
We're gonna add
a little Worcestershire.
I have some salt here, too.
Would you like that?
I would love that,
thank you.
Now we're ready
for the Gruyère.
Whose recipe was this?
This is mine.
We're gonna add
a little cheddar.
Local goat cheese.
Local goat cheese?
Unbelievable taste.
Delicious.
Mmm!
I like the tang of that.
I'm gonna fold that in
and dump the pasta now.
We should probably
just test this.
I think we'll be fine.
Camera's not on, is it?
Cut.
We actually are gonna make
a little bit of a panko mixture
to put on the bottom
of the muffin tin.
Start with panko crumbs,
extra virgin olive oil,
add in
some fresh ground garlic.
Want me to hit this?
Yes, please.
Really good,
so they come right out easily.
Really good.
Like, really good.
A little fresh
parmesan cheese.
So that little
mixture now.
Now we're going to fill it.
Just fill a little bit
on the bottom of each.
While you do that,
I'm just gonna make sure
that nothing has changed
over here on this.
[ Laughs ]
Still okay.
Now we blind-bake this off?
Yep, we brown
for about a minute.
Now we're going to fill them.
[ Laughs ]
What?
You sprinkle that on top so it
gets a little crunch on top.
Bake them off.
For about 8 to 10 minutes.
10 muffins in a basket.
10?!
Ohh!
It's like culinary Christmas.
Look at that little mac and
cheese nugget-slammer-popper.
Shut the front door.
Just enough
to hold it together.
And whatever of the fat
of the cheese that melted
got captured down here
in the little panko zone.
The key is the outside
crunchiness.
This is like an extra week now
at the gym.
You're the bomb, Andi.
You got to try this one.
WOMAN: It's delicious.
It's a little crunchy
and then chewy. Ay.
FIERI: Does everybody in Phoenix
know about this?
WOMAN: It's still
a little underground,
but more and more people
are finding out about it.
You can't beat it.
It's just The Duce.
[ Bell rings ]
I want to see
these two in the ring.
Let's go!
FIERI: Coming up...
That's a big, hearty taco.
...we're headed to Leucadia,
California...
It's funky enough
that if you're not a local,
you might not stop.
...for the sun, the sand,
and the taco stand.
Take that to go!
[ Bell dings ]
This is doing it
"Triple D" style.
I'm 30 miles north
of downtown San Diego
in a little town called Leucadia
right on the 101,
right by a gigantic
railroad track,
and just a few blocks
from the beach
to check out
a funky little joint
that is serving up
a Southern California staple.
This is Haggo's Organic Taco.
You know you're gonna get,
like, fresh, fresh meals.
You can tell he really knows
his flavors.
FIERI: 'Cause owner
James Haggard, a.k.a. Haggo,
spent a decade managing
a high-end resort kitchen...
I was in close quarters
with the chefs always.
So I just sat back and watched
them all the time.
Then you escaped.
Then I escaped.
...and opened his own joint
in 2011...
...with a mantra that reads,
"Fresh and organic."
Minimum 95%, and sometimes
it hits as high as 98%.
That means tacos with everything
from free-range chicken
to grass-fed beef.
But you know,
being this close to the water,
it's all about the fresh catch.
How far are we from the beach?
A couple blocks?
Yeah, a couple blocks.
He makes a brilliant
fish taco.
I guess when you call it
the Cousteau,
you should have "brilliant"
somewhere in that name.
Cousteau Taco.
Inspired by Jacques Cousteau
himself.
So what would he eat
the most of
if he's out on the Calypso
out to sea?
Well, I'm out on a limb.
I'm gonna say fish.
There you go.
Okay, hit it.
Fish tacos.
I make the spice rub --
oregano,
onion powder, cayenne,
paprika,
black pepper, sea salt.
This will go on the fish.
Excellent. Next up.
Next up is crema,
which is sour cream...
two tablespoons of cumin...
[ Whistles ]
Salt and lime juice.
Yes.
You got the dry rub
for the fish, the crema.
Next up?
Let's go.
Let's cook the fish.
Halibut -- Californian.
Got a little bit
of our dry rub.
So, I'll let this saute.
Tortillas go down?
Yep.
Flip the fish.
It's nice and blackened.
Finish it off.
Looking nice in there.
That's a big, hearty taco.
Put the crema on here.
A little cabbage slaw.
Salsa cruda.
Mango, yeah.
Good-looking fish taco.
I love cilantro.
Rice and bean it.
This is
just mouth-watering.
I can see your saliva
right now.
There you go.
Tasty.
Hot and tasty.
That's bordering
into a gourmet fish taco.
Everything's in balance.
Slaw's great,
the fish is really fresh.
Not over-seasoned.
You can actually taste
the fish in this.
Nice salsa,
a little bit of crema,
good cumin coming through.
Mmm!
That is a rock-star fish taco.
Well done.
Very nice.
Well done!
Mmm!
Take that to go!
FIERI: You've had a few
fish tacos in your day?
I've had many.
This is right at the top.
It's delicious.
It's one of my favorite spots.
MAN: It's just a funky local
establishment.
You want to keep those going.
It's funky enough
that if you're not a local,
you might not stop.
Yeah.
Out of leaving your career
of 11 years in hospitality,
you figured,
"You know what? That's it.
"I'm trading in the tie,
and I'm gonna get a t-shirt
and build funky organic tacos
next to a train track."
All-American dream.
Word.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
to the Mount Airy neighborhood
of Philly...
That's nice.
...for the unexpected taste...
I want to lay down in it.
[ Laughs ]
...of some South Carolina
cooking.
Official member of Flavortown,
without question.
So I'm here in Mount Airy,
Pennsylvania,
about eight miles northwest
of downtown Philadelphia,
to check out a joint
where a former Philadelphia
fine-dining chef
has gone out on her own
to open up a joint
serving innovative
low-country cuisine.
This is Geechee Girl Rice Café.
Out of the oven.
It's just yummy goodness.
I think about it
before I get here.
Tostones.
The food is just over-the-moon.
FIERI: And it's based
on the African-inspired
low-country cuisine
owner Valerie Erwin grew up on.
Geechees are the descendants
of the enslaved Africans
who lived on the coasts
and in the islands
off South Carolina
and Georgia.
And while Val's cooking
honors the Geechee culture,
she ain't stopping there.
I really like
traditional food,
but I don't think that food
is immutable.
Immutable?
Don't use those kind
of big words with me.
Un-changing.
Thank you.
And a great example
is this best-selling dish.
North African chicken.
Val's take on a traditional
African meal.
WOMAN: I've never had chicken
like this.
It's like a combination
of a lot of different cultures.
What's the first dish
we're gonna make?
We're making
North African chicken.
Chicken quarters rubbed with
cumin and oregano and garlic.
Let's roll.
Cumin, dry oregano, salt,
pepper, minced garlic.
Right in
with the dry spices?
with the dry spices.
It gets mixed together,
and then olive oil.
Squeeze, squeeze,
squeeze, squeeze.
It's got to
really make a paste.
I gotcha.
Next up?
Salt and pepper
the chicken.
So it gets rubbed
on both sides.
Kind of massaged into it.
A little bit.
Olive oil.
We're just gonna put a little
brown on both sides of it.
Whoo, that's strong!
Oh, look at that.
Now I want to saute
the citrus.
Really?
This is getting
more interesting as we go.
Now back in these? Okay.
So a little bit of water,
which will cool down the pan
and also just give a little bit
more de-glazing liquid.
And then orange juice
and lemon juice.
This is all gonna
go in here.
Just cooks like this.
It cooks like this.
Into the oven for an hour.
Yep, at 500.
Next up?
I'm sauteing collard greens
that have been blanched.
Okay.
And adding
caramelized onions,
sautéed peppers,
and some minced garlic.
Couscous-style
Carolina gold rice.
And then a little bit
of the sauce
that the chicken
was cooked in.
That's some tender chicken.
Wow!
That's a great flavor.
I wouldn't even know how
to really describe the flavor.
The oregano and the cumin
aren't as strong as I thought.
They kind of mellow out.
Yeah, they do mellow out.
It's refreshing,
super-tender.
It's just a really nice, light,
but well-rounded flavor.
Mmm! You just want to go
back in there for more.
And then you come
to the greens.
Those are up there with the best
greens I've ever had.
Awesome texture.
They're super-flavorful.
That's a phenomenal dish.
I'm so happy you like it.
Wow!
I am so happy
you made it.
There's all these flavors
that develop as you eat it.
I absolutely love the chicken.
What do you think
makes the food so good?
Val.
MAN: She's infusing
a little part of her
into everything that she cooks.
FIERI:
From her Princeton-educated mind
to the skills she perfected
as a fine-dining chef...
She brings in African flavors,
and she brings in Asian flavors.
FIERI: ...and for this dish,
she brought in some of the
Carolina flavors she grew up on.
Pulled pork.
[ Bell dings ]
We're gonna make pulled pork,
and it starts with a spice rub.
Got it.
Brown sugar, chili powder,
paprika, garlic powder,
cayenne, salt,
and dried thyme.
Mixy-mix?
You want the pork?
Yes.
This is a picnic shoulder.
Yep.
The top of it
is the pork butt.
That's up here.
This is the picnic shoulder.
You let this go overnight.
Let it absorb the flavors,
okay?
We are gonna tea-smoke this.
It starts
with ground white rice.
So you grind up the rice.
You grind up the rice.
It just makes it
easier to burn.
Coarsely ground pepper,
sugar,
and tea
from an iced-tea bag.
This is a new one for me.
Tea-smoke mixture in the bottom,
and then put a rack in it.
Put the pork on the rack.
Cover it with foil.
Make it really tight.
This is gonna be
like meat Jiffy Pop.
And it'll run for an hour
on a medium heat.
Whoa!
So after it's all smoked,
take the meat out,
put it into a pan
with some water,
and then I cover it
with plastic wrap.
Plastic wrap,
then aluminum foil.
Put it in the oven and cook it
for three to four hours
until it's really tender.
Now we've got it.
It's had its chance.
Yep.
Thank you.
I take off
the skin and the fat.
I can tell that you've pulled
a pork in your time.
I've pulled some pork
in my day.
And then I season it
with hot sauce.
There you go.
Cayenne pepper.
[ Imitates alarm blaring ]
And a little bit of salt.
Mmm!
And I just put in a little bit
of the braising liquid,
which has the pork flavor
and some of the smoke flavors.
Is there more that comes
with this meal?
I'm fine just this way.
So it comes with coleslaw,
and this is
barbecued black-eyed peas.
And cornbread.
That's nice!
That's just delicious.
That little tea smoke in there
with that vinegar,
a little bit of that cayenne.
Mmm!
That's good, old barbecue-pit
food right there.
And you don't even need
a pit.
I want to lay down in it.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN: Pulled pork.
MAN:
I always look at the menu,
but then probably half the time,
I end up with the pulled pork.
Here's the deal --
We're hanging out
at Mount Airy, Pennsylvania,
with Chef Valerie.
When we come back,
she's gonna make a dessert.
What's it called?
Sour cream pound cake.
See you in a little bit.
Welcome back -- "Triple D" here
in Pennsylvania in Mount Airy,
right outside
of downtown Philadelphia,
hanging out with Chef Val.
And I got to tell you
something --
This has been
an experience.
Now to finish out
this culinary adventure,
what are you making?
I'm making
sour cream pound cake.
So, this is a family recipe
from my Aunt Netta,
who was a great cook.
Make it happen.
Butter
at room temperature.
So we're gonna cream it.
We're gonna cream it.
Sour cream.
Now I'm gonna add
the sugar.
That's gonna cream
for a while.
Combine the salt
and the flour
and just mix it up
a little bit with a whisk.
And now I'm gonna
beat the eggs.
So I'm gonna start adding the
flour and the eggs alternately.
Want me to slurp
some of the eggs in?
Yeah, just about half of them.
I used the word "slurp."
And that's it.
Bake this at 325,
and it takes an hour and a half.
Okay.
So it's had a chance
to cool down now.
Mm-hmm.
And then it gets
a little bit of whipped cream
and a little bit
of powdered sugar.
And that's it.
That's it.
Mmm.
This is my kind
of dessert.
I don't like dessert
to be too sweet.
I hate when it's
so light and fluffy
that it doesn't
have texture.
That you can't taste it!
I know!
There's a little tang to this,
a little richness to it.
Put some strawberries
on that. Ohh.
Blackberries.
Forget about it.
Collard greens.
Put some collard greens
right on top of that.
WOMAN: I don't know exactly
who Aunt Netta was,
but I would have loved her.
Thank you so much.
You're really welcome.
You got to come meet
Chef Val.
Official member of Flavortown
without question.
So, that's it for this trip.
But don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughs ]
How do you get the sprinkles
on top?!
[ Laughter ]