Hey, everybody!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
How do things look?
...I'm pushing the Camaro
to the limit...
Oh, not good
for the "Triple D" car.
...in the hunt
for some killer "Q."
This is a pretty interesting
brine.
You just wait.
In Compton, California...
How are we looking?
...the backyard joint
serving up their take on ribs...
Want to try some of this?
No, I just thought
I'd just sit here
and watch you just bring
them out and tease me with them.
...and the real-deal
collared greens.
It is legit as they come.
In Philadelphia, Pennsylvania,
the southern spot...
Cry about it.
I know.
It gets me every time.
...stuffing sandwiches
with barbecue's best cut...
So we're gonna give it
the flat top, much like you.
That's not flat.
That's --
That's irregular.
And in Denver, Colorado...
Now we go!
There you are!
...the husband-and-wife
pizza parlor...
Good luck and good luck.
...going pie high...
Hang on.
I'll go get the kitchen sink.
...with beer-braised brisket.
[ Whistles ]
That is monster, man.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, you're looking for
a killer barbecue joint.
How do you find it?
Well, you could read about it,
a friend could tell you
about it,
you could watch some crazy show
about a dude
driving all over the country
trying great food,
or you could sniff it out.
That's why I drive
a convertible,
and that's what's led me here
to South Long Beach Boulevard
in Compton
to check out some killer
barbecue at Bludso's.
It's off the chain.
Pulled pork on a bun with
a baked bean and hot sauce.
Hands down it's the best
barbecue in Southern California.
Texas-style barbecue.
FIERI: And Kevin Bludso's
got a reason for that.
My granny had a little small
shack in Corsicana, Texas.
Every summer, my
mother and father would
send me down there...
To learn
the ways of the pit --
Lessons he shared with
family and friends for years
when he was off duty.
What were you doing
before you opened this place?
Working for
the Department of Corrections.
Seriously?
Yeah, yeah,
corrections officer.
In L.A.,
he made the jump and went --
no pun intended -- whole hog.
Kevin is barbecue.
That's all he talks about.
MAN: Kevin puts a lot of love
into his work,
and I'm telling you,
you can taste it.
Best ribs in town.
The spicy sauce here
is to die for.
What are we making, boss?
Spicy barbecue sauce.
So, hot water.
Chopped onions.
Chopped garlic.
Chopped jalapeños.
Whoa!
Kind of let that cook
for a little while,
warm it up a little bit.
And we got
our tomato paste.
And we whisk that around
a little bit.
Next up.
Chili powder.
Mustard powder.
Salt.
Granulated garlic.
[ Whistles ]
Sage.
Dark-brown sugar.
Crushed red peppers.
Whoa!
This is gonna be spicy.
Black pepper.
Just a little cayenne.
Come on!
Just a little.
Got to stir this up
a little bit.
Next up.
Now we gonna get our wet --
Cider vinegar.
Smoque.
A little liquid smoke.
Worcestershire.
Soy sauce.
Molasses.
Thick and sticky.
Oh, yeah.
Now, how long
is that gonna cook down?
We let it cook down
for about three hours,
and then we let it sit
overnight.
We strain it in the morning.
FIERI:
So, the sauce is legit.
But you know good barbecue's
got to have some righteous rub.
All right, so give me
the rundown.
Okay, a little brown sugar.
White sugar.
Seasoning salt.
Chili powder.
Granulated garlic.
Coarse black pepper.
Okay.
Cumin.
Cayenne pepper.
Oregano.
Okay.
Granulated onion.
All right.
We got to mix that up.
That's a good-looking rib.
And this is
the Compton trim?
Yeah, this is
the Compton trim.
And then we cut
the brisket bone off.
When we cut mine,
I just take it all the way down.
Typically, when you trim it
all the way down
almost to where it's uniform
all the way across the top,
that's the St. Louis trim.
The Compton trim,
on the other hand,
is just barely taking off
the top of those bones.
Okay.
There's still some good meat
up here at the top.
Oh, delicious meat.
Delicious meat.
We gonna rub it down.
And you're gonna let it set up
for 24 hours.
In the cooler for 24 hours.
That's the way to go, man.
What kind of wood
are we running?
We're gonna run some red oak
and some pacaya.
What temperature
are we running?
250.
250 for how long?
About 3 1/2, 4 hours.
Want to try some of this?
No, I just thought I'd sit here
and watch you
just bring them out
and tease me with them.
I thought you just came to hang
out with me for a little while.
[ Whistles ]
Right from
Fred Flintstone.
I'll tell you what --
this is a righteous rib.
Not too much smoke.
Just all that flavor
just coming out of that bone
onto that pork.
That nice crust, that bark.
Get a little bit of that
red in there -- that's
coming from that smoke.
That mean barbecue sauce we made
with all that tomato paste.
Whoo!
Like the heat on that?
A little heat in that.
[ Laughs ]
That's got nice spice.
A good little kick
of that vinegar on the back.
A little bit of that dry mustard
coming through.
Man.
That sauce is smoking-good.
WOMAN:
And seasoned just right.
You taste the smoke.
What's your favorite?
The sides.
The sides are homemade.
Got your green?
Yes, sir.
MAN: Kevin's mother
must have taught him
'cause it seems to have
come out right.
Now what are we making?
Collared greens.
Grandma's recipe again?
No, this is my mom's right here,
really.
Mom's recipe.
Yeah.
Every Sunday, collared greens
at the Bludso house.
So two of those.
Chicken base.
Chopped garlic.
Chopped onions.
Chopped yellow peppers.
Smoked turkey necks.
Smoked turkey necks?
Yeah.
Okay, we let our necks
get tender,
so we let it cook down
for about an hour and a half.
Now what are we doing?
We're gonna add our collars.
[ Whistles ]
So these have been washed.
This is gonna cook down to...
When are we gonna add
the rest of this?
We're gonna add seasoners
right now.
Crushed red peppers.
Onion powder.
Season this up.
Now, how long are we gonna
let these go?
About an hour.
Nice and tender?
Nice and tender.
How are we looking?
We're good.
You want to try
some of this?
Will you get me with some extra
turkey neck in there?
Oh, yeah.
Those fingers
don't know any heat pain.
I hear you, baby.
Shut the front door.
[ Laughs ]
Ohh!
All it needs to say is
"Bludso's Greens" out front.
That's cool.
I want to get in there.
I'm gonna crawl
all in that pot of greens. Mmm!
They're tender...
a little bit spicy.
They're rich.
Great broth with them.
Not too salty.
That's just
the right balance, man.
Awesome.
Glad you like it.
Kev, great greens, man.
Collards up.
WOMAN: Tender.
That's how I like my greens.
They're flavored
very, very well.
Delicious, man!
Give me at 250.
Bludso's is number one
in Compton.
And Bludso's is doing it well.
You got to come down to Compton
and try it. You really do.
Well, I'm gonna tell you
something, buddy.
It is legit as they come,
but if they don't want to come
all the way down to Compton,
are you gonna open up L.A.?
We're opening up
on Melrose and La Brea.
You're messing with me.
No, not at all.
Is Melrose and La Brea
ready to handle you?
They're gonna have to be.
With greens like this,
this guy can go international.
The bomb.
FIERI: Up next...
Identical.
We're headed to the
City of Brotherly Love...
Are you taking it
to a fashion show?
What in the world?!
...for a Texas taste
of down-home "Q."
I'm almost drowning
in my own saliva.
So, I'm here in Philadelphia
looking for
some real-deal
"Triple D" barbecue.
Now, I've found it
all over the country.
I mean, you go to
Fairfield, Connecticut,
you got Wilson's.
You go to Chicago,
you got Smoke.
You go all the way out
to California to Venice Beach,
you got the crazies
from Baby Blues Barbecue.
Word on the street is you're
looking for barbecue in Philly,
you got to check it out
here at Percy Street Barbecue.
O'SHEA:
Spare ribs in the window.
Out of this world.
O'SHEA: Lamb ribs are up.
Best barbecue in the city.
Plain as that.
FIERI: And it all started as
a hobby for owner Erin O'Shea.
All of my barbecue is like
hanging out with friends.
That's the way to do it.
And after years of working
in other people's joints,
she decided to open her own,
bringing Texas-style barbecue
to the people of Philly.
Most of the meats are smoked,
and it's dry-rubbed,
so the flavor
just comes from the meat.
Chopped brisket sandwich.
The brisket's delicious.
What are we
getting started with?
This is the brine
for the brisket.
We're gonna start with
salt,
sugar,
bay leaves,
garlic,
all spice.
A lot of it.
Yes.
Caraway
and water.
This is
a pretty interesting brine.
You just wait.
So we're gonna
bring this up to a boil.
How long
are we gonna simmer it?
Just for a few minutes.
We're just looking to
dissolve everything.
Okay, we've strained our brine
and let it cool.
We're gonna take our brisket
and trim it up.
So, we're gonna give it
a flat-top, much like you.
That's not flat.
[ Chuckles ]
That's irregular.
So, here we go. We're gonna
take a little bit of the point.
Are you taking it
to a fashion show?
What in the world?!
[ Exhales sharply ]
These are gonna
go in brine.
I have never,
in my history
of doing barbecue,
seen this done.
Really?
So, we're going to
brine this guy.
How long will this brine?
This is gonna go
for about 36 hours.
And this is all going
for a brisket sandwich?
Yes.
So 36 hours,
and then we go to
the smoker.
Yes.
And red oak.
Red oak.
And that's it.
Nicely done.
How long's
that gonna go?
That's gonna go
for about five hours.
Word.
All right. These are
the brisket pieces.
Cry about it.
I know.
It gets me every time.
So, we're gonna
chop them up.
So this reminds me
more of burnt ends.
That is the most
burnt-end-tasting...
wow.
Wow. That's tasty.
So, we're gonna
chop it up...
add some sauce.
Do you make
the barbecue sauce?
I do.
Of course you do.
Of course I do.
[ Chuckles ]
There we go.
Hey. I'm in this.
A little fresh onion
and some
bread-and-butter pickles
to finish it off.
That's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
All the
connective tissue's
basically just
melted into the meat.
Great pickles,
a little bit of onion in there.
Mmm!
That's ridiculous.
That's real-deal barbecue,
girl.
Nicely done. Excellent.
Thank you, sir.
You got to try that.
It just falls apart
when you eat it.
MAN: I've had barbecue
from the Carolinas to Kansas,
and this stands up to
some of the best I've ever had.
FIERI: So, we know Erin
does traditional barbecue right.
Spare ribs in the window.
FIERI: But how about something
a little unconventional?
When I saw that
this was on the menu,
I said, "Okay, I got to
see this. This is different."
...when we come back.
FIERI: We're parked
at Percy Street Barbecue
on 9th and South Street
in Philly...
...where owner Erin O'Shea
clearly knows her way
around a smoker,
whether it's
a classic brisket platter,
glazed lamb ribs,
or something a little outside
the typical barbecue box.
Pork-belly sandwich
in the window.
Okay,
what are we making now?
We're going to
start the process
for our
belly sandwich.
This is pork belly
that we're gonna brine.
Okay.
In we go. Brine on top.
Same brine that we used
for the brisket?
It's similar,
but it's not much caraway.
How long are we gonna
let it brine?
12 hours.
And then are we gonna
salt it?
Salt and pepper,
in the smoker.
Hit it!
All right.
How long
is that gonna go?
About three hours -- 250.
[Voice breaking ] Goodbye.
[ Laughs ]
We'll cut it
into quarters.
Now we're gonna slice it.
Mm-hmm.
About this style.
Very liberal with this.
Big-boy pieces.
So, you can see -- I mean,
it's just breaking apart.
You've rendered down
the majority of the fat.
Oh, my goodness.
What happened here?
Oh, it's falling apart...
in my mouth.
Oh, how'd that happen?
Now we're gonna grill it and
put it on a sandwich?
Yeah.
Hurry.
Okay.
Sweet Thang
barbecue sauce.
Little pickled carrots
over here?
Yep. Spicy carrots.
Okay.
Cilantro.
And belly.
I'm almost drowning
in my own saliva.
Mmm!
Wow!
The pork's rendered down.
There's still
a little bit of fat in there.
It's really nice and juicy.
The barbecue sauce
is out of bounds.
It is just
tons of flavor,
and everybody
works well together.
Oh. Ohh!
Nice.
I love it.
This is gonna be
a go-to for me.
That is
a phenomenal pork sandwich.
Oh, thank you.
Mmm!
Great texture, great
layer of fat, great flavor.
WOMAN: It has a little bit
of a sweetness to it,
but it has, like,
a good, nice burn.
You are awesome.
I don't know
what you're doing
next time
you come down to Philly,
but I'll tell you
Percy Street
definitely deserves
a visit.
You're gonna love it.
Killer. Mmm!
FIERI: Coming up...
Get all maestro
on me there.
...we're headed to
Denver, Colorado...
Wow.
...for a tongue twister...
Beer-braised beef brisket.
FIERI:
...of a barbecue pizza pie.
[ Laughter ]
Say that five times fast.
How do things look?
Oh, not good
for the "Triple D" car.
Well, anyhow,
I'm here on Tennyson Street
in the Berkeley neighborhood
of Denver.
Now, this is
a real cool little street
with all kinds of eclectic shops
from art galleries
to hair salons,
hardware stores -- You name it.
So you wouldn't be too surprised
to find out
they got an eclectic
little "Triple D" joint
that's serving up hand-crafted
beers and handmade pizzas.
This is Hops & Pie.
Bacon, pineapple, jalapeño.
The pizza here is top-notch.
FIERI:
Whether it's classic pepperoni
or righteous arugula
with fig compote...
It's just flavors that you
won't get in other places.
They really do, sort of,
open your eyes
to a different experience.
FIERI:
'Cause for husband-and-wife team
Drew and Leah Watson,
pizza is a way of life.
We're East Coasters
originally.
Grew up in places
where every block or two
had their own pizza shop.
Now, these two fine-dining vets
are cranking out funky pies
like this barbecue-inspired
tongue twister.
The beer-braised brisket pie.
Beer-braised brisket pie.
Say that five times fast.
All right,
so we're gonna make dough?
We are gonna make dough.
Okay, but the interesting part
about your dough
is you include beer in it?
We do include beer, yeah.
Fire it up.
Now we go!
There you are!
Flour goes in first.
Next goes in our house beer --
Hops & Pie P.A.
Water's next.
And then the yeast.
Okay.
Get that in there,
then we crank her up,
we turn it on,
and then we slowly add the oil.
And then since we've got
the yeast in there,
it's starting
to do its magic.
Now you can add your seasoning
with your salt.
Yep.
Generous with that.
Got to have it.
We age our dough
three days.
Really? So hold it cold.
Hold it cold.
Really build
that yeast flavor.
Yep.
Now we're into?
Corned-beef brisket.
We're gonna make the brine.
First, water,
Hops & Pie P.A.,
ground ginger,
chili flakes,
anise seed,
juniper berries,
coriander seed,
caraway seed,
mustard seed,
fennel seed,
peppercorns.
This is an interesting one.
[ Chuckles ]
Star anise, bay leaves.
Hang on.
I'll go get the kitchen sink.
[ Laughs ]
I don't know if it'll fit.
We got kosher salt,
brown sugar,
cinnamon stick,
raw onion, and lemons.
And how long
are we gonna let this simmer?
We just bring it
to a boil.
Once everything's melted
and kind of worked together,
we hit it with the ice
to cool it off,
and we put it
over the brisket.
And how long are you gonna
let it sit there and pickle?
7 to 10 days, depending
on the size of the brisket.
Got it.
So we've brined.
Now it's time.
It's time to braise.
Okay.
Brisket in.
Gonna take some of the aromatics
out of here.
Water.
And then beer.
Plastic wrap and foil.
Okay.
In the oven for how long?
What temp?
300.
5, 6, 7 hours.
whatever it takes.
When she's falling apart.
Okay.
Got the brisket here.
Cooled down in its juices.
Beer-braised brisket.
Wow.
So now what do we do?
We're gonna cut her up.
Cross grain,
nice and thin.
That's about a pizza
right there.
[ Whistles ]
All right,
let's make it up.
All right.
Put down some semolina.
A lot more semolina on top.
A little for good luck.
Get it in there.
Now we're gonna
roll out the dough,
and then after that,
stretch it by hand.
That's a nice-sized pie.
Yeah.
Next our sauce.
The house-made sauce.
Mozzarella cheese.
You got all maestro on me
there.
A little parmesan on there,
as well.
Little parm.
All right,
and then we go for the brisket.
You dealing poker
or making a pizza?
Smoked pork loin...
Mmm.
...Applewood smoked bacon,
smoked pork shoulder,
and ham hock.
A little more cheese,
just to hold her together.
Just to decorate on top.
Yep.
This is gonna go in the oven
at what temp?
475.
475. For how long?
6, 7 minutes.
Depends on the pizza.
Pig pie.
Looking good.
Here we go.
[ Whistles ]
Okay.
All right.
Clarified butter
on the crust.
It is a monster, man.
That's a good-looking skin
on there.
That dough
is just remarkable.
It's light, it's crispy.
You get a little bit of a hint
of the beer coming through,
and then all the meat's on it,
so you get some sweet meats.
The brisket is strong.
It's got that real bitterness
to it.
But it's counterbalanced
by the sweet tomatoes,
the bacon, the cheese,
all of that together.
So you get
all these contrasting flavors.
That's dynamite. Nice job.
Thank you.
Really nice.
WOMAN: You need to get out of
the burbs a little bit more.
I mean, what's not to like?
Fantastic beers, fantastic food.
FIERI: It's a great place.
Good energy, good vibe,
great beer selection,
killer pizza.
Denver's lucky to have you.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Sorry.
[ Laughs ]