Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Let's get it on!
Get it on!
...we're sticking a knife
into the craft movement of meat.
I am a big fan
of that.
In San Carlos, California...
Load up the car.
...the Belgian beer pub...
Wait till you see this.
...perfecting pastrami...
The things I got to do
for you guys at home.
...and taking on
a Philly legend.
You sure you want
to go through with this?
Got to go to Philly,
bro.
The culinary assassin.
And in Portland, Oregon...
Good to go.
...a righteous
Americana joint...
Get after that!
...going whole hog
tip to tail...
That should be illegal
right there.
...right next to great-grandma's
legit fried chicken.
Ready for your life
to be changed?
Let's go,
buddy.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I love food, and I know
that's pretty evident.
But there's particular types
of food that I really dig,
and pastrami's one of them.
I'm talking about old-school,
real-deal pastrami,
the kind of pastrami you get
on the East Coast
when you go to Katz's Deli
in the Lower East Side
of Manhattan.
So, if you're on the West Coast,
I hear you got to go
to San Carlos, California,
right between San Francisco
and San Jose
and check out this joint --
The Refuge.
Swiss and mustard.
Everybody is over the moon
about the pastrami here.
The Reuben.
It just really literally
melts in your mouth.
What do you think of this?
It's the best.
Like, you'd have a wedding cake
made out of pastrami.
Oh, yeah.
MAN: It must be the ingredients
or the love
that they put into it
that makes it fantastic.
FIERI:
It's a little bit of both
'cause owner Matt Levin's been
working to perfect his recipe
since he was 16,
and the pastrami old guard
was no help.
Deli guys are -- They'll kick
you right out of there.
I had to figure it out myself.
FIERI: So he brought in
his own heavy hitter,
Chef Michael Greuel...
Tell me he doesn't look
just like a culinary assassin.
...to give old-school pastrami
a try on the West Coast,
and they're piling it up high
on this sandwich.
Toasted slaw 19.
The flavor's
just amazing.
You can't beat it.
So, what are
we gonna make?
GREUEL: We're gonna do
the Toasted 19,
our pastrami sandwich.
So, it brines
for a week,
then it gets coriander
and black pepper,
and then it gets smoked
with hickory.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
We're gonna throw it
in the steamer now?
Okay, first,
we're gonna get the drip pan
'cause we're gonna use this
for the lacquer
that we're
gonna make later.
The what-er?
The lacquer.
All right, fire it up.
But we've got to steam it
for four hours.
Steam it
Mother Mary.
Okay, somebody should get in
some heavy sponges
'cause this --
Wait till you see this.
If you don't have anywhere
to put that,
you can put that
in my car.
[ Laughs ]
Look at that, just tender.
Michael,
that's outstanding.
Whoa-oh, whew!
You put the drippings
in the pan.
Brown sugar.
Black pepper.
And a cup of coriander.
Correct.
Then reduce it.
We're gonna reduce it more?
Yes, by half
'cause it's making a "lacquer."
A "lacquer."
Okay.
Let's do this.
Then we trim off
all the fat.
Look at that.
What I do is I section it off,
dip it in the lacquer.
Then we slice it.
For every sandwich?
Every sandwich.
[ Laughs ]
O-M-G.
This is a different level
of ridiculous.
So, now I'm toasting the bread
on the flattop.
Okay.
Build it.
You got Russian dressing,
coleslaw, Swiss.
And then
we put the meat on.
There you go.
Yeah.
This is ridiculous.
You could be
a hard-core New Yorker --
Nothing's gonna prepare you
for that.
It's that good,
man.
Really nice toasted rye.
Perfectly brined,
smoked, steamed.
It's that good.
I'm not kidding ya.
Night-night.
I just sort of crave it
once a week.
WOMAN: Literally just
falls apart in your mouth.
It's a fix. [ Laughs ]
FIERI:
Addicting as it is,
some people don't even come here
for the food
because they also are known
for having 18 Belgian beers
on tap.
MAN: The pastrami
and burgers and fries
just seem to go great
with Belgian beer.
FIERI: Speaking of pastrami,
burgers, and fries,
Michael and Matt decided
that's a killer combo, too.
The pastrami burger.
We're making the patty
for the pastrami burger.
Very nice.
I'm basically
gonna cure the meat
with salt and pepper
before I grind it.
So, I'm gonna let this cure
for a little while,
and then we're gonna put it
in the grinder.
Okay, fire it up.
Beautiful red color --
The meat was almost
at a frozen state,
so it goes through nice,
doesn't smear the fat.
That's it?
One run?
One run.
Nicely done.
And now
we'll make some patties.
All right, so,
I put some oil down.
It's gonna be a half pound
of burger meat.
Seriously?
And why in the oil?
Because we're gonna put it
on the flattop next,
and it helps preserve the meat
a little bit more,
and it also gets it
so it doesn't stick to the pan.
Throwing down
the butter first.
Butter?
Big burger.
I'm gonna get a nice sear
on it.
I'm gonna press it down
just a little bit.
Look at that.
Throwing down some butter.
That crazy
Russian dressing?
That's the crazy
Russian dressing.
Okay, I'm gonna slice
the pastrami now.
I dipped it
in the lacquer.
That's gonna go
on the base.
Melted Swiss cheese
on the burger.
Oh-oh!
Top it off
with a little sauerkraut,
a little more
Russian dressing.
The things I got do
for you guys at home.
It's intimidating.
It's rather large.
The pastrami
is ridiculous.
The burger
is way out-of-bounds juicy,
and the lacquer
is ridiculous.
I like the pepper
being incorporated into it.
I mean,
it's dynamite, man.
I just have nothing
to say. Awesome.
Nice job.
Thank you.
It's amazing.
Just melt-in-your-mouth juicy.
Just tastes delicious.
FIERI: I've had
a pastrami sandwich
that almost
has taken me out.
But when we come back,
the culinary assassin
is gonna let loose with what?
Cheesesteak Wit.
See you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
Hanging out
with Chef Michael
here at The Refuge
in San Carlos.
Now, we have just had
a pastrami experience
that is something
of another world.
But the man
says I can't go
'cause I got to stick around
for the...
Wit Cheesesteak.
The Wit Cheesesteak,
okay?
So, with
or without cheese,
Philly cheesesteak
but made here on the West Coast.
So, you sure you want
to go through with this?
Got to go to Philly,
bro.
The culinary assassin.
I got
a rib eye here.
Beautiful rib eye.
I'm gonna take off
all the silver skin and fat.
So we're gonna break it
into pieces,
freeze it, slice it?
Correct.
Excellent.
What are we into now?
We're on to making the...?
Now we're gonna do
the cheese sauce.
First, we're gonna start off
with the roux.
Okay, so,
some butter.
We're gonna cook the roux
until it's nutty.
We're gonna put
a little bit of color on it.
We're gonna go
to tan?
Yeah.
Flour goes in.
Okay, and letting that go
a little bit.
Okay, and then
I pour in the milk.
Give it
a little stir.
When it starts to simmer,
then I add the cream to it.
I assume that's
"meg of the nut," or nutmeg.
Correct.
The salt.
Thank you, bro.
There we go.
Tabasco.
Ooh, I like that.
Okay.
As you can see,
it's almost thickening up here.
When it comes
to a simmer,
then I can start
adding the cheese.
This is
really dynamite cheddar.
He's owning it.
There we go.
Dude!
We should
probably taste it
just because that's
our fiduciary responsibility.
Mmm.
Um-nom.
Just give me a bowl of that
and stick me in the corner.
Okay, next?
Throw down
the soy oil.
I hear in Philadelphia,
that's how they use...
The soy oil?
Okay.
It's very particular.
And then
we're gonna cook my meat
with a little salt
and pepper.
There you go.
Come on.
There you go!
Hey!
While I got that going,
I'm gonna go
with some cherry peppers
and some
caramelized onions.
Okay, now,
this is gonna be key.
Watch, watch, watch,
watch, watch, watch!
Ah, now you're going
all authentic on me.
Sauce it up.
Nicely done,
governor.
I got anything
right there?
Am I okay?
A little bit.
[ Laughs ]
One,
the flavor's great.
The cherry peppers...
...are outstanding.
The cheese sauce
is on point.
The meat's super tender.
The roll's got
a little bit more crust to it
than a typical Philly roll,
but it's still the light
and airy roll
that, even though there's
a ton of moisture in there,
it's not soaking through
and falling apart on you.
You win
with the Wit.
The cheesesteaks
are out of this world.
I live and die
by the cheesesteaks.
WOMAN:
The sauce is amazing.
It's money.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Laughter ]
Used my word.
Super impressed.
Not often
I can say that.
Thank you.
All right,
load up the car.
FIERI:
Up next...
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
...we're headed up the coast
to Portland, Oregon...
Throw some music to this,
please.
...where a chef's
doing his own butchering...
Full nelson.
...to bring out the best bites.
It's like opening up a present
at Christmastime.
From Pig Santa.
I'm here in Portland, Oregon,
in the Montavilla neighborhood,
looking for a joint that I hear
does the bomb fried chicken.
But I tell you,
I've been warned.
Watch out for this chef.
He's nose to tail,
farm to table,
and his menu is off the hook.
This is The Country Cat.
Authentic
Southern-style cuisine.
ADAM:
All right, sausage in a pan.
It's just real food.
FIERI: But at The Country Cat,
it goes way beyond that.
Look at that baby. Man!
FIERI: Since '07, Missouri-born
chef Adam Sappington
and his wife, Jackie,
have been digging up
some serious culinary roots.
It's American-heritage
cooking.
We've taken
the old recipes.
We've updated them.
I wanted to bring
the craft-cooking aspect back
and put it into the technique.
FIERI: A technique that uses
every part of the animal.
They break all their animals
down themselves.
And for you, sir,
the Whole Hog.
It is an art form,
the Whole Hog --
a pork chop, pork shoulder,
rolled, brined,
cured pork belly,
fried headcheese.
When you say
whole hog,
you are getting a portion
of the whole hog.
Yeah.
What are we doing
with these?
That's a trotter.
That's gonna basically go
into the headcheese.
You got belly.
And then
the loin chops.
Where your pork chop
is coming out of?
Yeah, exactly.
Let's get it on!
Get it on!
Straight across.
Aah!
Full nelson.
Okay,
here we go.
Got my belly section.
[ Laughs ]
Get after that!
Ay, ay!
Make it
your dinner!
Here we are
with this big monster chop.
And the rest
of the loin.
And what are we creating
out of this now?
The porketta
for the plate.
Okay, so, now we're
gonna take this and brine this?
Cure it.
We're gonna cure it like bacon
for five days.
Kosher salt.
Pink salt, brown sugar,
white sugar.
Ginger.
Chili flake, Cayenne,
a little combo.
Now I'm gonna grind up
black pepper,
juniper berry,
coriander.
Look at that.
Parsley,
thyme, a little sage.
Good to go.
Go here
on the parchment.
I kind of
massage it in.
Just push it down.
You really are
gonna press it.
So, a bunch
of number-10 cans.
Put it
in the walk-in.
Let it go five days?
Mm-hmm.
Then roll it.
And then roast it 2 1/2,
3 hours, 300 degrees.
[ Whistles ]
Check it out.
So, there's our beautiful
porketta.
It's like opening up a present
at Christmastime.
From Pig Santa.
You got to eat that.
I'll let you eat it.
[ Chuckling ]
Right?
Now what are we gonna do
with it?
We're gonna put it in the pan
and sear it up.
And this is just the beginning
of the pork platter?
We are just beginning.
The brined,
cured pork chop,
smoked and braised
pork shoulder,
with Moyer prunes,
and the porketta.
It's time.
Okay, so,
South Carolina grits,
a little red
and green chard,
a little bit
of braised shoulder, porketta.
Chop.
These are Willamette Valley
prune plums.
It's keep-on-moving sauce.
It is.
And...
The cornmeal-crusted
fried headcheese.
That's correct,
my man.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
That is gorgeous,
huh?
I'm gonna try a little bit
of that shoulder.
[ Laughs ]
By itself,
that is ridiculous.
The grits --
Forget about it.
Now, remind me again,
on this gigantic chop.
Brined 24 hours.
Mmm.
Now I'm gonna get a little bit
of this porketta.
Amazing flavor,
incredible texture,
all coming
from the same animal.
I'm gonna get some
of this headcheese.
Dude.
That's the deal-sealer
right there.
MAN: This is not
your normal pork chop.
The porketta --
It's just fabulous.
It's rich, it's briny,
it's porky, it's fantastic.
This is one of the best
pork dishes I've ever had.
Thank you so much.
And I came here
for the fried chicken.
[ Laughs ]
It is always
about the fried chicken.
I learned
how to fry chicken
from my great-grandmother
Maude Marie Murphy.
The three "M."
She used to fry chicken
for inmates at this little jail
in Vienna, Missouri.
Give me the rundown.
Real simple brine -- salt
and water for 24 hours.
And I debone
the chicken.
I get them
24 hours after harvest.
Oh, this is
some farm-to-table program,
as well, with the chicken?
Oh, 100%.
Now we're gonna take them
and hit them in the brine?
Plop, plop,
fizz, fizz.
24 hours, and another 24 hours
in the buttermilk?
Yes.
Ready? Dredge.
Flour first
in the paper bag, salt,
lemon pepper,
and then onion powder.
Got it.
Granulated garlic,
then celery seed.
Then I give it
the old shaky.
Throw some music to this,
please.
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Laughs ]
So, I do it
in batches.
The thigh,
my favorite piece.
I'm a big thigh guy.
Okay.
Let it set up
for about three hours?
Then we'll fry it
in the beef and pork fat.
This is how you do it
old school.
ADAM: Make sure your fat's
nice and hot.
Thigh first.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
And how long
is that gonna take?
Takes about
12 to 15 minutes.
Ready for your life
to be changed?
Let's go, buddy.
Sour cream
mashed potatoes --
a little bit of potato,
a whole lot of sour cream.
Country gravy.
Thigh.
Parsley.
[ Whistles ]
This is
for a little color.
Yow.
None of that
fork-and-knife stuff.
[ Laughs ]
It's everything...
...you want fried chicken
to be --
tender, juicy,
it is crunchy.
It's more complex
than the average fried chicken.
I just got to see if I can get
the one quintessential bite --
mashed potatoes,
a little chunk of that bacon.
There's some salad.
[ Laughs ]
That should be illegal
right there.
WOMAN:
It's so amazing.
I keep coming back for it.
It is to die for.
FIERI:
And then go to heaven.
There, you'll find another one
of my favorites...
Beef jerky.
I love jerky.
...when we come back.
FIERI:
Welcome back.
Hanging out in Portland
at The Country Cat
with the crazy butcher,
Chef Adam.
FIERI:
This dude's breaking it down
from whole hog
to full sides of beef,
and he's using every last scrap
to make some American classics,
including one of my weaknesses.
Hand-cut beef jerky.
Doctor, doctor,
give me the news.
This is
the rear hind leg.
Going right for
the eye.
You see that?
Yep.
I'm getting all the way down
to the bone,
just exposing that muscle.
This is the piece
that we have for jerky.
That's a big eye
of round.
I'll portion it out.
Right? And then
I'll freeze it.
So it's easier
to slice?
Yeah.
We're gonna make
our cure.
Kosher salt.
Brown sugar, sugar, celery seed,
onion powder, black pepper.
Boom, boom.
Garlic granules,
a little chili.
Okay, mixy, mixy.
Make sure
that all the brown sugars,
you know, incorporate in
and it's not lumpy.
I just lay it out nice
and thin.
So thin
it's only got one side.
Whoa!
Hit both sides,
and then how long
are we gonna let that sit?
24 hours.
24.
Lay them out
in the dehydrator.
We're good to go?
Yeah, we're ready to roll.
Yeah, dude. Right?
Meat candy.
This is a little bit
on the sweet side...
Yeah.
...but not
that it's shy of salt.
I love jerky.
Mm-hmm.
It's one of my vices.
You're killing me.
[ Laughs ]
Hand-cut beef jerky.
MAN:
Kind of peel it off.
A little bit of spice
but not too much.
Excellent.
I can't believe all your friends
don't weigh 500 pounds.
[ Laughs ]
Got to meet this guy.
Just watch out.
He's dangerous.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Do you want me
to put anything on,
like a medieval helmet?
You want one of these,
dude?
I don't know
that I can rock that.
Mine will look like
I was born in it.
[ Laughs ]
Swaddled in it.
I'll just pull it up
at the back.
Whoo!