I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
It's bomb?
It's bomb.
...we're settling in for some
full-blown family time...
This is gourmet
right here, man.
...a double dose
in Nashville, Tennessee...
This girl been cooking.
...where a food-truck couple...
We got
some Tennessee cheddar.
It's a monster.
...is flipping out
on the grilled-cheese concept...
I'm gonna go into, like,
a little dream sequence.
...and a down-home
Italian joint...
Rustic, baby.
...is dishing out the goods
on grandma.
Look at that.
Then, in Kansas City,
Missouri...
It's spicy.
...the family noodle shop...
Who's a better cook --
you or your sister?
Of course my sister.
She's right over there.
...laying out the wizardry
of the won tons.
For scientific purposes,
I'm gonna have eight more.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So I'm here in Nashville,
Tennessee. Got to love it.
I mean killer barbecue,
great music,
and you never know
who you'll run into.
So anyhow, I'm here
to check out a joint
that's doing grilled cheese,
but grilled cheese
to a different level.
It's not just
what they're serving,
it's what
they're serving it from.
Get this -- a food truck.
This...
Was that...? Nah.
Anyhow, this is
The Grilled Cheeserie.
JOSEPH: Pimento mac and cheese
melt, no bacon.
This truck is one of the best
food trucks here in Nashville.
B&B and tots.
FIERI:
And the word is out.
It's almost impossible to find
them without a long line.
We have two macs
on the grill.
It's not trying to be fancy.
It's just good and what's right.
Short rib melt.
FIERI: Translation --
gangster grilled cheeses
and standout soups.
A simple menu that
chef Crystal De Luna-Bogan
and her musician husband,
Joseph, have stuck to
since they opened the truck
in 2010.
The sandwich is like heaven
in your mouth.
I heard from other folks in line
this is your anniversary.
MAN: Yeah, it is.
I like the way you roll.
This place does it right.
Great ingredients
from local farms.
So it's gourmet grilled cheese,
but it's still,
like, a comfort food.
FIERI: With awesome combos like
short ribs and pepper Jack,
cheddar with bacon,
and this funky top seller.
Two pimento mac and cheese.
Partnered up with their take
on the classic tomato soup.
It's nice and cheesy and gooey
and hot and spicy.
We got
some Tennessee cheddar.
It's a monster.
It's a 40-pound block.
We're gonna cut this up,
shred it up for the pimento
mac and cheese base.
So you're gonna
cut the cheese?
I'm gonna cut this cheese
with this knife.
So no processed cheese
in this crew.
No, sir.
Mm. Delicious.
Okay.
So cheese is done.
I'm gonna make some mayo.
Eggs, garlic,
our spice mix --
paprika, cayenne pepper,
and then...
Hot sauce?
...hot sauce in the mayo.
It's a slow stream.
Slow stream.
And then the oil.
So this kind of replaces
the whole roux situation.
I got you.
This actually makes it
a lot more gooey.
And we love our mayo here
in the South.
All right.
Now we just assemble.
So we got our mac.
We already cooked it
into some salted boiling water,
a little oil.
We got our mayo made.
Whoa, this girl -- think she
was pretty, little bartender.
This girl been cooking.
[ Chuckles ]
And then
here comes the good stuff.
Got our cheese.
I'm digging it.
You just want a little bit of
noodle just for some texture,
but it's mostly
about the cheese.
Righteous.
And then we're just gonna add
our roasted peppers.
So that's basically it.
All right. Let's go.
We're gonna make
the famous tomato soup
that goes along
with the pimento mac and cheese
grilled cheese.
Yes.
Little oil.
Gonna start
charring these onions.
Okay.
Fennel seeds,
chili flake, garlic.
We're just gonna sweat this out,
get some color.
San Marzano tomatoes.
So just roasted San Marzano,
a little bit of olive oil.
A little bit of olive oil
and some roasted red peppers.
And we're actually gonna add
a little bit of veggie stock
'cause this soup is vegan.
We're just gonna blend it
with our stick blender.
Fire in the hole.
Okay.
Leave it
a little bit chunky.
'Cause it's funky
when it's chunky.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
We're gonna put a little bit
of turbinado sugar.
And then we're gonna add
the baking soda,
which helps alkaline
the tomatoes.
And it brings out
all the flavors.
It's like night and day.
So how long are we gonna let
this simmer?
Just for 20 minutes,
and then it's good.
This is done,
sits there and simmers.
Now we make the sandwich,
put it all together.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Assembly time.
So we're gonna butter
the bread.
This is our special
butter mix.
Which is?
Butter and mayo.
I like it.
Pimento mac and cheese,
some of our beautiful
local tomatoes,
bacon bits,
and then we finish it off
with the same cheddar
that we've just sliced.
Then we go to the grill.
Yeah.
Get it.
And we press it down.
How long's that take
to melt?
About two and a half minutes
on each side.
It's all melty.
Cut them halfway.
We present it open-faced
so you can see
all the goodness.
Okay.
And we serve it up with some
of our house-made pickles.
So the roasted red pepper
and tomato soup.
Little basil oil on top.
Pimento mac
and cheese melt.
Rustic, sweet,
a little bit of spice.
That basil oil's the bomb.
I got to try this sandwich
by itself.
What'd you think
about that?
You know what?
I'll tell you something --
if you're left with just
mac pimento by itself...
Mm-hmm.
...it's really
not enough texture.
Yeah.
Texture was the word.
But you put the pasta
in there and the tomato --
a little bit of spice coming out
of that, as well.
This is where it goes on.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
That's how you do it.
This is so good.
I'm gonna go into, like,
a little dream sequence.
I am telling you what --
this just takes me back
to childhood.
It's a labor of love,
so we better produce, right?
They call it
"The Grilled Cheeserie."
[ Chuckles ]
We're the place
where grilled cheeses are made.
where dreams
about grilled cheeses
are fulfilled.
[ Chuckles ]
I got a pimento mac going out
with the soup.
You can never go wrong
with that combination.
So you've only been in Nashville
for a month?
And I've already eaten here
an embarrassing amount of times.
Seriously?
Yeah.
FIERI: Here, everybody's got
to wait in line.
This joint's even catering
to country star royalty.
I come to Nashville,
I expect to see, you know,
some superstars,
but Trace Adkins
at a grilled cheeserie.
This is gourmet
right here, man.
House-made pimento cheese,
local cheddar, macaroni --
that's this sandwich.
He reads the menu
of a food truck
and makes it sound like
a country song.
This is a food-truck mecca.
This does it.
This is it.
Trace, good luck on tour,
brother.
Thank you, Guy.
Appreciate it.
Wow.
Nashville -- what a town.
I mean, Trace -- I should have
given him a ride or something.
[ Tires squeal ]
Not again.
Coming up...
Hit it, Danny.
...we're staying in Nashville,
but headed to the house
that grandma built.
When I asked her
what she put in it, she said,
"A little bit of this,
little bit of that,
a little bit of this."
So I'm about two miles west
of downtown Nashville
on Murphy Road to check out
a joint where a chef,
who's a transplant
from New York City --
he's had a couple places.
You've probably heard of them --
The Dancing Bear,
The Red Rooster,
and for the last 15 years,
he's been rocking this place.
This is Caffé Nonna.
Pickup, table five.
I start craving it
through the week.
It's like I'm in Italy.
Really?
FIERI: Whether you're eating
meatball arrabiata...
The balance of the flavors
is just wonderful.
...or the seafood angelina...
The best Italian dish
I've ever had.
The home-style preparation
feels like
you're sitting
at grandma's house.
FIERI: So it's fitting chef
Danny Maggipinto named the joint
for the woman who first got him
into cooking.
My interest came from watching
my grandmother cook.
But, you know, she never
had any recipes,
so I used to try
to watch her.
And when I asked her
what she put in it, she said,
"A little bit of this,
little bit of that,
a little bit of this."
So while studying
at culinary school
helped him learn the science,
his nonna's at the heart
of every dish...
like his take
on her Italian classic.
We've got the lasagna.
FIERI:
Piled eight layers high.
Hit it, Danny.
We've got the filling
for the lasagna.
So what we have here is some
whole-milk ricotta cheese.
Okay.
Add the cream to it.
Shallots, garlic, sage,
dried oregano,
dried basil,
crushed red pepper.
Salt and pepper.
Then we whip it.
Whip it good.
See?
All right, so what
we're gonna do first
when we layer this
all together,
we're going to add
some marinara sauce.
Next -- lasagna sheets.
A nice, fresh lasagna.
And then we add some
of the ricotta mixture.
Add some spinach.
Put another layer down.
And we put the -- in the middle,
goes the butternut squash.
Rustic, baby
Some more layers of lasagna
going down.
Then again, we put some more
of the ricotta down.
That's a lot of ricotta.
A lot of ricotta.
Then we put some more
of the spinach.
What, the entire garden?
Very nice.
Yeah.
Another layer.
Okay.
All right, we put that on.
And then, to finish it off,
we top it with marinara sauce.
Awesome. I mean, I've made
a lot of lasagna.
I've never seen it
look this rustic.
We feel really good.
Hit it with
some parmesan cheese here.
We got some shredded mozzarella
right here.
Okay. This goes
in the oven how long?
400 degrees for about an hour,
hour and a half.
Covered.
So here's
our cooked-off lasagna.
Now it's ready to portion.
Look at that.
Now we put it in the pan.
Hit it with a little bit
of marinara sauce.
Okay.
Hit it with some reggianito
parmigiano, some mozzarella,
and then we put it in the oven
for 10 minutes.
All right, so this is
the finished product.
And what we do is
we put down the --
the mornay sauce has a little
bit of parmesan in it.
Take a little bit of Swiss chard
that's been steamed.
Then we take the lasagna.
There we go.
Little bit of marinara sauce
like that.
Wow.
Hit it with
some parmesan cheese,
a little bit
of fresh basil.
And then these are some
fried julienne carrots,
julienne zucchini,
and julienne squash.
Nothing wrong with that.
And that's all she wrote.
That's lasagna nonna.
And this is
the kind of lasagna
that your grandmother would
make when you were a kid?
This is sort of my version.
I wanted to put
a little spin on it.
You know what I like, is look
at the amount of spinach
this guy puts
on his lasagna.
Nice, big, thick noodles
in there.
You definitely don't hold back
on the cheese.
Three different sauces
in there.
I mean, you put a lot of time
and work into it.
Yes, sir.
It tastes like it.
Nice job, chef.
Thank you.
Really nice.
WOMAN:
We've got the lasagna.
It's delicious.
Extremely tasty.
FIERI: What was that?
It was the lasagna.
There's really not much left
of it now.
No.
MAN: They put themselves
into what they're doing.
And it comes out in the food.
FIERI: And for chef Danny,
it's more than just about
making his customers happy.
He's also cooking in the memory
of his daughter Zoe.
MAGGIPINTO:
After she passed away,
I wanted to try
to figure out how
how I could I raise money
'cause it was a rare form
of brain cancer.
So he started the Zoe Marie
Brain Tumor Research Fund,
raising money for it
by selling his nonna's marinara
to the public.
FIERI: If people want to help
out, is there a website?
Well, they can go
to cmft.org.
And if they want to get
your tomato sauce,
they can go online
at your place.
They can go online
to Nonna's Gourmet Foods,
and they can order it
through there.
WOMAN: He just creates amazing
food that is fresh and real.
So that's what we love.
I see why you're doing so well
and why Nashville loves you.
You got to check this guy out
and buy that marinara sauce.
nonnasgourmetfoods.com --
get more info.
Up next, we're headed
to Kansas City, Missouri,
for some sweet songs...
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
fry, fry, fry ♪
...and dibs on the dumplings.
Winner, winner, chili pepper
won ton for dinner!
Yeah!
So I'm here in Kansas City,
Missouri.
Now, I can almost promise you
I've been in this
neighborhood before.
Bookstore looks super familiar.
And if I'm right -- take a look
at this, right there --
that was Bell Street Mama --
a joint that we shot
in season three,
and then they moved
to a larger location.
I mean, to think, the place
I'm about to visit was here
at the same time I shot it.
I could have double-dipped.
I could have shot both.
Ugh.
I'm not gonna miss it this time.
This is Blue Koi.
It is traditional Chinese,
but it's a bit of twist...
Firebird chicken's ready!
MAN:
It's not Kung Pao chicken.
It's not
General Tso's chicken.
It's just a whole
different game,
whole different kind of food.
How you doing there,
Jane?
FIERI: ...'cause the Chang
siblings are serving up
Chinese-family recipes mixed
with big-time personality.
Chicken lettuce wrap!
Got it! Got it!
For brother Scott
working the front of the house
to sisters Jane and Mindy
cooking in the back.
Two order chili pepper
won tons here!
Okay, got it!
Who's a better cook --
you or your sister?
Of course my sister.
She's right over there.
We'll stick with Mindy for now
'cause she's cooking up one
of my all-time favorites.
Chili pepper won ton!
It's fabulous.
It's the perfect meal.
It's awesome.
It's bomb.
It's bomb?
It's bomb. Yes.
We need the soy sauce,
vinegar.
Is it rice wine vinegar
or is it regular vinegar?
This is regular vinegar.
Okay.
Yeah. Sesame oil,
white pepper, sugar.
Garlic?
Garlic. Yes.
Cilantro.
Lots of it.
They say you like cilantro.
We chopped extra for you.
Green onion.
And a home-made hot oil.
And we'll just stir.
And that's all she wrote.
Mm-hmm.
Fantastic.
Yes.
[ Whistles ]
Next, we're gonna make
chili pepper won ton filling.
Okay.
Ground pork.
Ground pork, ground chicken,
and chopped shrimp.
I like it.
A little bit of soy sauce.
Rice wine, sesame oil,
white pepper...
green onion.
Okay, and we'll just mix it
really well.
Okay.
Yeah.
And then we're gonna let it sit
for 10, 20 minutes
just to let it all
marinate together.
Marinate a little bit.
Okay.
Next?
We're gonna make
the chili pepper won ton.
There we go.
And we'll just kind of seal
the two sides.
Seal the deal.
Got it.
And so then that way,
the meat won't fall out.
Yeah.
Okay, and then put a little bit
on the side here.
There we go.
And just fold it.
And -- ooh.
All right.
That's when
the magic happens.
And that one's yours.
How many come -- wait,
what are you doing?
You know how many I make
of these at home.
I just want to see it,
you know, with my own eyes.
You want to see it
with your own eyes?
Yeah.
I don't think mine
looks right.
Is that right?
Yep.
Okay, so now we're gonna
pan-fry these?
Yep.
And I like it crispy.
All right, then we'll just
make it extra for you.
We ready to go?
Yep. Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Nice and crispy for you.
There you go.
And we're gonna put this
awesome sauce in there.
There you go.
Mm. I love the vinegar smell
in that.
Little sweet, little heat.
These are awesome.
Mm.
This dipping sauce
is ridiculous.
Now, as everybody at home knows,
I'm a huge Chinese-food fan.
So just for scientific purposes,
I'm gonna have eight more.
Awesome job.
Yes.
Winner, winner, chili pepper
won ton for dinner
at Blue Koi!
Yeah!
They're incredible.
Quite a nice kick.
FIERI: So what do you think
makes the food so great?
Love.
Love for sure.
MAN: They've really become,
like, the family that I have
in the city.
There's no "hello, goodbye."
It's just like
I never really left.
All right,
so here's the deal --
we're hanging out at Blue Koi
in Kansas City, Missouri,
making -- you got it --
Chinese food.
So we have two sisters.
We're gonna cook
with the next one.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Kansas City at Blue Koi.
Now this is Jane,
and I cooked with Mindy.
But now Jane's
Mindy's sister,
and they share
the same birthday,
but different year.
Did I get that right?
That's correct.
I'm so confused.
So, Jane,
what are we gonna make?
Okay, we're going to make
the firebird chicken
on noodles.
Firebird chicken's ready!
The firebird chicken is my
favorite -- really good stuff.
WOMAN: You get a little bit
spicy. You get some sweet.
It's stuff you can't get
other places in town. I love it.
Firebird chicken.
Right.
We need to marinate
the chicken first.
Marinate the chicken?
Yes.
Got it.
Sliced chicken breasts.
And then we need to add
a little bit of water into it
because you need
to massage them.
You massage the chicken.
Until all the water go
in the chicken.
And then we add
some cornstarch into it
so the moisture
will be held into it.
Massage, massage, massage,
you know?
Is that a massage song
you're singing?
Yeah. Yeah.
To the chicken.
And they are happy,
so my customers --
they are very happy, you know?
That's how we cook.
You're as crazy
as your sister.
[ Laughs ]
And then a little bit
of ginger onion oil
we make in-house.
And then that way,
when you cook,
they don't stick together.
Got it.
You got to brown
both sides?
Brown it both sides.
And then I put the noodles
in the water.
That you make here
in-house?
We make in-house.
So we'll add some seasoning
in there.
We put the garlic
and the rice wine.
Here comes fire.
"Here comes fire."
Now we add the sugar,
soy sauce,
Chinese barbecue sauce,
nice red pepper.
That you make here
in-house.
We make in-house.
Red chili.
A little bit of chicken broth
into it.
And bamboo shoot in there
and the green onions.
Our chicken's ready,
noodles ready --
we're ready to plate.
So we'll put a little bit of
our house-made ginger onion oil
and a little bit of soy sauce
into the bowl
and pick up the noodles.
See what I'm saying?
Look at that.
You don't see that everywhere.
And we toss them.
Firebird is ready.
Going to be fire.
It's spicy.
Very spicy.
It's fire -- that's why
it's called "firebird."
Fire.
Too hot. Too hot.
Another song.
Ha ha ha ha.
Ah -- ah --
Kidding.
[ Laughs ]
Mm.
There's some heat.
No question.
The noodle is awesome.
Nice texture to it.
Al dente.
Everything you want --
a little spice,
a little fresh veg,
great texture of the noodle,
super tender chicken.
Not typical Chinese food.
You got to come try it.
It's just so good. It's kind of
got, like, this smokey,
like, Asian barbecue flavor.
I've been coming here
about nine years.
I come like
three days a week.
It's like eating
in someone's kitchen.
Firebird chicken!
Jane, that looks wonderful!
It's just amazing comfort food.
Nice job.
Yes!
You got a song for me?
It goes ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
fry, fry, fry ♪
There you go. Come on down
for the musical.
So, that's it for this road
trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Wow!
Nailed it!
[ Laughter ]