Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Growls ]
I got something in my hair.
...we're giving thanks
for what else...
Wait for it!
...the best holiday around.
ALL: Happy Thanksgiving.
FIERI:
In Albuquerque, New Mexico,
the one-of-a-kind bakery...
You could have been
a taxidermist.
...doing their take
on the turkey.
It tastes like holiday
right off the bat.
North, in Santa Fe...
Call me the soup rabbi.
...a man with many names...
Now you're
the priest of pie.
The king of cookies.
The sultan of sandwiches.
The duke of soup.
[ Laughs ]
...going legit
with the leftovers.
I have to roast
like three extra turkeys now
just to make this.
And in Kansas City,
Missouri...
Look at that.
...the barbecue joint
basted in family tradition...
And that's all she wrote.
...stuffing the smoker
with the standards...
Tender, tender --
I'm on a brisket bender.
...and doing a turn
on the big bird.
I'm gonna go
all King Arthur on it.
It's a little messy,
but you can do it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
[ Turkeys gobbling ]
So, it's Thanksgiving time.
Now, on "Divers, Drive-Ins,
and Dives,"
I have traveled
all over this great country,
meeting all types of folks
celebrating this holiday
their own way.
So here I am in Albuquerque,
New Mexico,
where a father-and-son team
have been baking up New Mexican
specialties since 1972,
and wait till you see
the type of turkey they bake.
This is Golden Crown Panaderia.
It's a fantastic
family-oriented bakery.
We feel really lucky to have
them right around the corner.
Great food, great
customer service where
you feel like family.
FIERI: And they definitely know
how to make a guy feel welcome.
Chris and Pratt are the best.
FIERI: The father-and-son
powerhouse behind this joint.
It all began in '72,
when military man Pratt Morales
got after
what he really loved to do.
PRATT: I always wanted
to be a baker,
and everywhere in the world
that I traveled in the military,
I always wound up
at the local bakery.
And it took
just another 30 years
to get a reliable
business partner.
I couldn't afford a C.E.O.,
so I raised my own.
Together, they turn out
a one-of-a-kind menu.
It's all about
the biscochitos here.
I like the pumpkin empanadas.
FIERI: But when it comes
to Thanksgiving...
Isn't that beautiful?
...it's no surprise that
the bird is absolutely the word.
Turkey bread is great.
They make it look
just like a turkey.
Okay, what are
we gonna make?
I want to make some dough.
And this is gonna be the wheat
part of the turkey...
The wheat part.
...which is the leg,
the drumsticks, and the wings.
Got some nice
stone-ground wheat flour.
This is the bread flour.
A lot of gluten in here.
Put a little bit of salt
in there.
A little bit of shortening.
And let it mix
for a little bit.
Some molasses. That's gonna
give us some of the color.
It's also some
of the sweetener, too.
And to soften up the dough
a little bit,
we're gonna put
some honey.
Darling.
Beautiful.
And now we're going to add
some water to it.
I'm gonna add it slowly,
little by little by little.
Time for the yeast.
We got all the mixes in there,
so here we go.
We stop it,
bring it all out here.
And what I'm gonna do now
to make a turkey --
It's gonna be made
in three parts.
I'm gonna cut
the drumsticks.
The wings is gonna be
about 1/2 a pound.
There you go.
I have another dough
that I need
to make the white
part of the turkey,
which is the breast.
White flour,
a little bit of sugar,
salt, the shortening.
Gotcha.
Water.
And add the yeast.
Well, here we go.
Okay.
How long
have you been doing this?
About 40 years.
40 years
you've been making these?
Yes. Mm-hmm.
Oh, this is gonna be
the drumsticks.
I see it.
They're dark meat.
And then we're gonna do
the body,
which is the white part
of the turkey -- the breast.
And this is gonna go
right in here.
Seriously?
Okay. And I'm gonna twist it
like this.
Now we're gonna do
the wings.
Now we're gonna cut
the top part of the turkey,
separate it.
There you go.
And then the wings.
Separate them over here, also.
The bone.
Could have been
a taxidermist.
Giving it
a little texture.
There you go.
And I'm gonna do
a very light egg wash --
Give it the golden color.
Some rosemary.
A little bit of parsley.
Let it rise
as high as it will.
Wait for it!
Ready?
[ Drumroll ]
Ta-da!
Here we go, guys.
Look at that.
That's beautiful.
Isn't that beautiful?
I think people would
like to have a turkey
that looked that good.
I'm gonna slice you a piece.
How is that?
I'd like to have
some of the knee.
A little knee
right there.
Mmm.
Great crust on there.
I get a little bit
of that molasses.
There you go.
Try some of the breast.
There's a good part
right there.
It has huge crust on it,
but then it's just pillowy soft
on the inside.
I get a little bit
of that rosemary on that --
On that bread.
It tastes like holiday
right off the bat.
MAN:
It looks good on your table
with your flowers
or whatever you're doing.
MAN #2:
It's a great place to come
and feel like you're welcome
all the time.
There you go.
Pratt, amazing.
Thank you, my friend.
I love it.
FIERI: Coming up...
So, you're kind of pimping
when you're crimping.
I'm pimping
all the time.
...we're headed north
to Santa Fe for a hidden deli...
Got it. Love it.
Can't wait to try it.
...ladling out
a post-feast favorite...
I'm done shooting.
I'm just eating the soup now.
...and one savory slice.
Look at that.
Just like Thanksgiving.
So, the Thanksgiving tour
continues
here in Santa Fe, New Mexico,
in the East Capitol
neighborhood,
where there's a "blink
and you'll miss it" deli
that you got to check out,
where they're rocking
award-winning soups
and keeping it traditional
with the pie.
This is the Back Street Bistro.
The food is superb.
It's awesome.
Order up!
It's home cooking.
I could eat here every day.
What do you think makes
the place so great?
Well, David.
-David.
FIERI: That's David Jacoby,
a Brooklyn transplant
who made his restaurant dream
a reality back in '94
and has been making
a name for himself ever since
with deli sandwiches...
Corned-beef Reuben,
avocado Amish cheese.
FIERI: ...scratch-made pies...
Coconut cream,
peach-crumb pies.
FIERI:
...and standout soups.
My friend Sydney that comes in
here, he's a rabbi,
and he said,
"What can we call you?"
I said, "Sydney, we'll
call me the soup rabbi."
He goes, "I love that."
So, why soup in Santa Fe?
Contrary to popular belief,
it is cold here in the winter.
FIERI: And just in time
for the holidays,
the soup rabbi's blessing us
with an award-winning recipe...
One bowl
smoked-turkey wild-rice.
FIERI: ...chock-full
of Thanksgiving favorites.
Conjures up thoughts
of, like, family.
It's like a home away from home,
you know?
Mmm.
Let's get into it.
Okay. We're gonna start with
one whole smoked turkey.
Hit it.
Take all the meat
off the bone.
This is the beginning of
my smoked-turkey wild-rice soup.
It was the winner of the
Souperbowl of Soup Cook-off
held every year in town.
The Souperbowl of Soup
Cook-off.
That's correct.
Cube the meat.
On to the turkey soup.
We're gonna make the stock.
Start with bones, skin,
everything that's not
in the meat pot.
Got it.
Add the water.
And this is just
to make the stock?
Yes.
Liquid smoke...
Whoa!
...just to fortify it
a little bit.
And I have
my chicken base.
Any garlic salt?
Nope.
And onto the stove we go.
And how long
will that simmer?
That's gonna cook
for four hours.
I like it.
Next step we have --
Take our stockpot.
We add our butter.
Melt that down.
We're making
a mirepoix roux?
That's correct.
Or our roux with mirepoix.
We add our onions,
carrots, celery.
And I begin to cook.
Okay.
Then we'll add
that flour in?
That's correct.
Incorporate the flour.
Great.
Cook about 15 minutes.
Cook the flour flavor out.
And then we'll add
the stock.
Nice.
I'm gonna boil this
for around 15, 20 minutes,
till the vegetables
are tender.
Next up?
We're gonna blend
everything together.
Take my blender.
[ Blender whirring ]
It looks like
a boat motor.
Okay, pretty much there.
[ Whirring stops ]
[ Whistles ]
Now that everything's
blended together,
I'm going to add
my cooked wild rice...
Okay.
...our turkey meat,
my roasted red peppers.
Not chili peppers?
No. These are
sweet red peppers.
Gotcha.
A little pinch
of white pepper.
And now
I stir it together.
Look at that.
Now I'm adding my cream.
Now the milk.
And there you have it.
I always think turkey and soup
or chicken and soup --
I always think about it
being brothy, not creamy.
That's creamy. How long
does it take to heat up?
About 20 minutes.
Got it. Love it.
Can't wait to try it.
Here's your
completed product.
Look at that.
This is the soup recipe
that won Souperbowl of Soups?
That's correct.
I think I'm with everybody
that says Thanksgiving --
You better not eat
all the turkey,
'cause you need to have
leftovers.
And one of my favorite leftovers
is turkey soup.
Mmm.
But I got to be honest --
I've never made it...
creamy.
I love the texture
of the wild rice in there.
And the smoke flavor
from the turkey.
But here's the key --
Because of the roux and
the pureeing of the mirepoix,
he was able
to thicken it up.
You add a little bit
of silkiness to it from
the milk and the cream,
but this is not
a cream soup.
Outstanding.
I see why it won.
I have to roast like three extra
turkeys now just to make this.
Sorry.
Smoked-turkey wild-rice.
It's really creamy and rich.
Like a wholesome country soup.
Turkey doing you right?
Turkey's doing me right.
The flavor's excellent.
So there's no doubt --
The food's legit,
but there's one thing
you'd think would hold
this place back.
This location's
so easy to find,
with its one window
and its little door.
Mm-hmm. We don't call it
"Back Street" for nothing.
David's place
is kind of special.
It's kind of hidden,
and it's hard to find.
You blink,
you'll miss it.
Yeah.
FIERI:
What you need on your phone
is a good map app.
And swing by in the fall
when this slice of heaven's
coming out of the oven.
Here's
your pumpkin pie, sir.
Thank you very much.
It's delicious. It's just like
my nana used to make.
Mmm.
Okay, let's get into it.
Okay, we're gonna
first make the dough,
starting with
3 cups of a.p. flour.
Okay.
A pinch of salt.
Super-cold butter?
That's it.
So then you create
the flakiness.
I start pulsing.
Then I add my 6 tablespoons
of ice-cold water.
Okay.
It goes immediately
into a bowl.
I will chill it
a little bit.
Just put it in the cooler.
About a half an hour.
Pull it out.
And get it
all squeezed together.
Cut in half
and begin to knead.
Form it into a ball.
Wrap it in the plastic wrap.
Wrap it up.
Flatten it out.
Put the pie crusts in the
refrigerator for the night,
and in the morning
it's relaxed.
Butter, butter, butter,
butter, butter, butter.
That is gonna make it
flaky, flaky, flaky,
flaky, flaky, flaky.
Once it's rolled out,
I like to tighten up the
edges a little bit.
So now we get that in there.
There we go.
And you're making your edge,
and you crimp.
So, you're kind of pimping
when you're crimping.
I'm pimping all the time.
This is to do
the blind baking.
That's correct.
I've never had tinfoil
on my pie before,
but if he says it's good,
I'll try it.
In goes your weight --
beans, usually.
In the oven.
What temp? How long?
375 for 25 minutes.
Crust is baked off.
I'm ready
to make the filling.
Start with salt,
cinnamon,
clove, ginger,
nutmeg, brown sugar.
That is
one flavorful filling.
Give that a little heave
together.
I'm gonna add my pumpkin.
Not pumpkin-pie filling?
This is just cooked, pureed,
straight-up pumpkin.
First mix this together.
Now I add my three eggs.
My molasses.
Molasses?
Molasses.
Evaporated milk.
And you want to
incorporate it real well,
'cause you want to get
those eggs working --
Fluff those up
a little bit.
Now I gently pour
into my crust.
Wow.
And then you put on
your --
That little ring
is gonna save that crust.
Right. Saves the edges
from overcooking.
Then into the oven it goes
for about one hour at 375.
All right, here we are.
Our pie
is cooked and cooled.
It's time for topping
of the whipped cream, okay?
This is whipped cream
that I have made.
You take a tremendous amount
of appreciation in what you do.
I put my heart and soul into
everything I do at this place.
I do try and use a pie...
cutting-gauge-measuring
thing.
I'll precut the filling.
Very precise.
Look at that.
Just like Thanksgiving.
Take a look at that.
Mmm.
I'm gonna tell you
something --
I have kind of
removed myself...
from pumpkin pie.
And I'll tell you why.
'Cause it don't taste
anything like that.
Oh, man!
Did we put ginger in that?
Yes, we did.
[ Whistles ]
This eats savory, almost,
because of the richness
of the spice.
Not overly sweet.
And creamy.
[ Sighs ]
Wow. That's dynamite.
That's great
pumpkin pie, man.
The pumpkin pie.
I love this pumpkin pie.
MAN: It's great.
It's just the right amount
of sweetness.
It tastes like Mom made it.
FIERI:
You're a restaurant machine.
I was born to be
in this business.
This is what you love.
I love it.
So, we got
the soup synagogue,
and now you're
the priest of pies.
The king of cookies.
The sultan of sandwiches.
The duke of soup.
[ Laughs ]
We're out!
FIERI: Up next...
That's generous.
...we're headed
to Kansas City, Missouri,
for a barbecue joint...
Now, that utensil
is far undersized.
...going to the birds
for the holidays.
I still think you should have
made yourself a turkey, Danny.
I really feel bad,
taking this all to myself.
So, here we are
on the final stop
of the "Triple D"
Thanksgiving Tour.
Now, we're in Kansas City,
Missouri.
Now, to check out
this next joint,
I had to invite
some real barbecue aficionados.
That's right --
My bros from my team,
Motley-Que.
And this is Danny Edwards
Boulevard BBQ.
Let's go eat.
Well, if you like good barbecue,
you come here to eat.
This is the place?
This is the place.
Sauce that bird.
Sauce is on.
Barbecue's been in
the Edwards family for decades.
FIERI: Starting with Danny's
dad, Jake Edwards,
who opened the first joint
back in the early '30s.
MAN: My parents used to take me
to Jake Edwards' Barbecue
downtown in the '50s,
and then Danny had
a couple of places downtown
and moved to this location.
FIERI:
Right on Southwest Boulevard,
where he's been smoking
and cooking since 2007.
MAN: Danny is behind the counter
when you walk in the door.
He's the man slicing the meats.
FIERI: All the usual suspects
like pulled pork,
beef brisket...
Hands down the best brisket
in Kansas City.
FIERI:
...and the November bird.
MAN:
The smoked turkey is excellent.
FIERI: Most of the year,
it comes on a bun...
Turkey sandwich, coleslaw,
rancher beans, and a jambalaya.
FIERI:
...but come holiday season,
he's selling the centerpiece.
MAN: So if you don't want to
bother to cook,
he's got them here for you.
FIERI:
Give us a rundown here.
Well, we're gonna put
the rub together.
Garlic salt,
black pepper, paprika.
Just enough
to do one bird.
Stand it up a little bit.
Put some in the cavity.
That's generous.
Okay.
Backside.
Bay leaves.
Oh, got to put the bay leaves
in the cavity.
Then that's all she wrote.
Let's go to the smoker.
Five hours, 265,
on hickory.
Here we go.
Let's go.
We got a little smoke going.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
Good-looking bird.
I still think you should have
made yourself a turkey, Danny.
I really feel bad,
taking this all to myself.
Look at this.
I'm gonna go all King Arthur
on it.
It's a little messy,
but you can do it.
A good piece.
Mmm.
The skin --
not rubbery.
And the turkey --
nice and moist.
Not too much smoke on it.
They smoke
from the inside out, too,
when you have
that cavity open.
That's good.
All right, let's put
the whole thing together.
Carve off a little bit
right here.
Got a little slaw
on there.
The rancher beans
go on that plate.
And that's good and hot.
Oh, yeah.
That utensil is far undersized
for this kind of food.
This is tender,
not overseasoned,
still nice and moist.
It tastes like turkey.
But I think perfuming it
with a little bit of wood
just adds so much to it.
I got a couple buddies
with me.
I want to see
what they have to say.
This is the crew
from Motley-Que.
We all met down at barbecue camp
down in Houston, Texas.
Smoked turkey? Come on.
Oh, it's really good.
Dark meat's really juicy.
Don't get your hands
too close to the cage.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Buy two turkeys --
One to snack on
on the way to the family event.
'Cause you know once you get it
to somebody's house,
you're not taking any home.
What else you got
up your sleeve?
The Big "D."
It's a great sandwich.
It's like
a barbecued Reuben?
A little bit.
Like that, only different.
A barbecued Reuben
with issues?
FIERI: When we come back.
FIERI: It's the last stop
on the Thanksgiving tour,
and the Motley-Que team and I
are loading up
at Danny Edwards BBQ
in Kansas City, Missouri.
I've got a burnt-end dinner
and coleslaw for Josh, please.
FIERI: I got to say --
I am tapped out on turkey,
so Danny's laying out one of his
signature barbecue originals.
All right,
I got a Big "D" up.
Brisket sandwich
with onion ring and cheese.
It's a great sandwich.
FIERI: That's all about
the point of the brisket.
The charred outside part
of the brisket.
FIERI: You have to cook
the whole brisket
before you can get
to the Big "D" point.
And you got to season
the whole brisket.
Get it going.
Start with sugar.
Seasoning salt,
garlic salt,
paprika, black pepper,
Cayenne pepper.
Is that a little accent
just got in there, Danny?
A little cumin.
Then we're gonna work it around
here and mix it up.
So, we're gonna
dry-rub this.
Fatty side on the top.
And this is all
for the Big "D."
Big "D."
Big trouble.
How long is this gonna go
on the smoker?
It's gonna go on all night --
about 16 hours, probably.
Really? 210, 212?
Now we're gonna separate
the flat of the brisket
from the point
of the brisket.
Flat. Point.
Right, and you can see
right where to do it.
There's a natural spot
to stick your knife.
I slide it
all the way through normally
and just follow the line,
and it goes straight down
about right there.
This will stay here.
This is the flat.
We'll use that
for brisket sandwiches,
and we'll trim this
just like this.
Your barbecue team
will like this.
Oh, yeah.
Now we can season this.
We're gonna hit it
with more seasoning,
so it's just right on its way
to being burnt ends.
Pretty close.
Now back to the smoker.
About an hour,
an hour and a half,
maybe two hours
at the most.
Hit it up, boss.
We're gonna make
the Big "D."
Get some of this really
beautiful stuff right here.
And we're
gonna start here.
Tender.
Tender, tender --
I'm on a brisket bender.
Put a little barbecue sauce
on that.
This is a little sauce
you make yourself?
Oh, yeah.
Now we're gonna put
this Swiss cheese on here.
We're gonna put
the onion rings on.
And that's the Big "D."
That's the Big "D."
That's the crown
of the brisket.
When you've cooked it
down perfectly,
and it just gets
to the point
where all the fat
is just cooked out,
it's basted all that meat.
This is a nice balance
between...
meat,
really nice toasted rye,
a little onion ring in there.
Nicely done, my friend.
Great job.
Thanks.
Big "D" pickup.
Big "D" special.
The brisket is just
melt-in-your-mouth.
It's so juicy.
The best brisket sandwich
in Kansas City.
I like Danny's.
It's pretty much the best.
It's number one.
I got Motley-Que sitting
at the table, salivating.
Time to see
what they think.
That is blowing my mind
right now.
I'm gonna use it
like a pillow.
Onion rings, Swiss cheese.
And it's a pillow.
Big "D" --
Off the hook.
That's my line.
[ Chuckles ]
So, that's it for this
"Triple D" Thanksgiving tour.
I'm telling you.
I am full.
But listen, we have so much
to give thanks for.
We are so fortunate to live
in the greatest country
in the world.
Hope you and your family
have a great Thanksgiving.
ALL: Happy Thanksgiving!
Smoky turkey.
Smokel-- smokel--
smoked turkey --
Smoked-turkey,
wild-rice.
It's creamy-turkey,
smoky wild-rice.
I'll start telling people
just like that from now on.
♪ Ba-ba
ba-dum-dum-dum ♪
Smoky-turkey,
creamy wild-rice.
[ Laughter ]