Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I've been tasting wrong
all these years!
[ Babbles ]
[ Chuckles ]
We're keeping it authentic...
Too legit to quit.
...with food's big three.
You got it --
Mexican, Italian, and Chinese.
Is it the real deal?
Yes!       Yes!
Yes!                        Yes!
In Santa Fe, New Mexico...
That's how I keep my peppers.
...real-deal Mexican
right on the chili highway.
It'll run if you chase it.
I'll chase it.
Down the road in Albuquerque...
Andiamo!
...a mom-and-pop trattoria...
Take a look in this, kids.
This is what you're gonna
be eating later.
...dishing up the eats
of Northern Italy.
It's no filler,
all thriller.
And in Portland, Oregon...
Oh, okay.
[ Murmurs ]
Oh. [ Laughs ]
...the family-run
Chinese joint...
Like spaghetti gone wild.
...turning me
into the noodle king.
Like a rocket ship
in Flavortown, baby.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here
in Santa Fe, New Mexico,
the desert high country --
one of the greatest
chili-growing regions
in the United States --
and I'm here to check out
a restaurant.
Now, get this --
The owner was born in the house
that turned in the restaurant,
and he's named the restaurant
after the small town
that he lived in
that grows great chilies.
Does that make any sense?
Doesn't matter,
'cause the food's the bomb.
This is
Casa Chimayo Restaurante.
GUZMAN: Chicken burrito,
Christmas sauce.
Really great,
authentic New Mexican food.
Red-chili posole
at the window.
This is it. You're here.
You have arrived.
A lot like walking
into your grandmother's house
or your mom's home.
FIERI: Or in this case,
Roberto Cordova's
mom's house.
You were born in this house?
Yes.
And you were raised in...
Chimayo.
The chili capital
just north of Santa Fe.
And after a career
in government,
his appetite for Mom's cooking
led him right back home.
She says, "Why don't you
just open up a restaurant,
"hire some cooks,
and I'll teach them
how to cook our way?"
That's exactly what they did.
In 2011, they brought in
self-taught chef Ernesto Guzman
to pick up where Mama left off.
It's the food of our ancestors.
We cook very simple.
It's home-cooked beans
and enchiladas.
FIERI:
Served six different ways,
including this classic.
GUZMAN: Chicken enchilada,
red-chili sauce.
So, what are we gonna make?
Chicken enchiladas.
Andale.
And we'll go ahead
and do a chicken stock,
adding water, celery,
carrots, onions.
Then we'll go ahead
and toss this chicken in here.
Garlic.
Okay. So, let this simmer.
These chilies right here
come from our farmer.
That's how I keep
my peppers.
You guys already feel
the [Sniffs] hot pepper
in your nose and everything?
So, when you see them
in the store,
you'll see it under the name
of New Mexico-style chilies.
Exactly.
And we deseed them.
We actually
break the tips off.
The real heat
is here in the vein.
Is in the vein right here.
These are very hot.
How many of these
you want me to do?
That's good.
We steep them in hot water.
Once we get them steeped,
we blend them.
This is gonna be
our Chile Caribe sauce.
Pour some of this hot,
steeping liquid.
I got some onions in there,
I got some garlic
I'm gonna add in there, as well.
Everybody in the pool?
And there it is.
This --
You go ahead and pour.
I'll do the pouring.
Strain this out
as much as possible.
Really just getting
the beautiful, silky --
just this rich --
Velvety texture.
Velvety. We'll use that.
That's done right there.
Now, how long
we gonna cook this down?
Oh, it's just a few minutes.
See how hot that is.
No, this is how you do it.
Yeah.
Oh, I didn't know
that's how you [Babbles]
There you go. [ Laughs ]
[ Chuckles ]
I've been tasting wrong
all these years!
[ Babbles ]
[ Laughter ]
But that's nice. I mean,
it's got a good, little heat.
Not overwhelmingly hot --
full-mouth hot.
Okay, so,
now what are we gonna do?
Since we've already had
our chicken stock boiled up,
this is what we're gonna use
for our stuffing.
And this is what we do
by hand.
Let's go ahead and add
some oil.
Heat that up a little bit.
Onions. Celery.
Garlic. Just sweat it,
basically, yeah.
And then add some tomatoes.
We're gonna add
this shredded chicken.
Basically, sauté that up
a little bit more.
Then we're gonna add
some chicken stock.
Gonna take three of these.
Okay.
So, these are
my blue-corn tortillas.
I really just want
to soften them up.
Then we're gonna take
our shredded chicken
that we just finished making.
Gonna add
some cheese inside.
This is that Chile Caribe sauce
that we made.
Look at that.
We're gonna layer these
right on top of each other,
bring it over
to the middle.
Gonna throw this right on top.
A little bit more.
Throw some cheese,
chopped onions.
Toss this
in the salamander
'cause we really want
to melt this.
Take this out.
Nice melted cheese.
I'm gonna add
some delicious pinto beans,
some of the rice.
Dig in.
Look at that.
This is hitting the spot.
You can taste the flavors,
especially the chili.
Not super-salty,
not really hot.
Velvety sauce,
good texture to the chicken.
The depth of flavor is huge.
This is all just real deal.
Simple,
but super-flavorful.
Exactly.
Excellent job.
Thank you so much.
The man.
Here are your red-chili
chicken enchiladas.
WOMAN: And it's just got
a whole bunch of flavors,
and every bite
gets better.
This restaurant
really represents
traditional, local food.
It blends
a lot of different cultures.
What he means --
It's a whole lot of goodness.
See?
It's always the girl
to just sum it up.
[ Both chuckle ]
Great place.
Great chef you have.
Food's delicious.
This has really been
a great experience,
and just the respect
and the admiration
for the chilies
and what a role the chilies
play in it, it's amazing.
You got it.
Thank you, brother.
FIERI: Up next...
Let it sing?
[ Hisses ]
We're headed south
to Albuquerque...
For everybody at home,
this is,
"Danger, Will Robinson."
...for what else?
Exactly.
Rustic Northern Italian.
FIERI: So, here I am,
about 20 miles northeast
of downtown Albuquerque,
New Mexico.
Now, this area right here --
kind of like a business park,
lots of office buildings.
And I'm here
to check out a joint
that is about as European
as they come.
Let's see.
The wife, she's from Italy.
The chef and husband,
well, he's from France.
And the food is off the hook.
This is Torinos' @ Home.
If I could, I'd be here
every day and every night.
It's like going back to Italy,
to family.
FIERI: 'Cause when Maxime
and Daniela Bouneuo
opened this joint back in 2010,
they modeled it after those
little family joints in Italy
called trattorias.
MAXIME: We don't want
to be expensive.
We don't want
to be a fine dining.
We want to serve honest food
at an honest price.
But that doesn't mean
they're cutting any corners,
especially
with this house special...
Order in.
A squid ink, please.
...a seafood dish
with tender calamari
and handmade pasta,
dyed with a squirt
of cuttlefish ink.
Mmm-mmm-mmm!
Okay. Andiamo!
MAXIME: All right, so we start
with semolina flour.
00 flour --
It's a very fine flour
that we use
for pastries, pasta.
It makes a harder, drier,
thinner product.
Right.
Salt. Eggs.
A little bit
of squid ink, of course.
Careful. It stains a lot.
If you ever wanted
to put permanent eyeliner
like you're a football player --
you know, the shade control.
You'll be good.
Just a little dash
of olive oil in there.
Low speed.
And stir water gently
in there.
And how long
are we gonna let this mix?
Oh, a few minutes --
just until
they bind all together.
I'm gonna speed it up
a little.
So, now we put the dough
on the table,
work it a little bit
by hand.
You see how black it is?
Gorgeous.
And then we'll roll it
in the pasta roller.
So, you roll it down
about by 1/16 of an inch,
and you keep rolling.
Look at the color on that.
I mean,
that looks like asphalt.
Nice shine to it.
And then we pass them
back on the machine.
But this time,
through the cutter.
Gorgeous.
Look at that.
And now we're gonna prepare
the sauce.
So, we have
a hot pan here.
We're gonna squeeze
a little bit of olive oil.
We're gonna grab
a couple calamari.
And we're gonna slice our tubes,
a few of the tentacles.
[ Oil sizzling ]
And we make some noise.
So, we're gonna let that sear
a little.
Okay.
Shallots and garlic.
So, we let that sweat in there
a little bit.
Heirloom tomatoes --
Those are coming
from right around the corner.
And at this point, I think
we can start seasoning --
a little bit of salt.
Fresh-cracked black.
And we need to be patient.
Let it sing.
Let it sing?
[ Hisses ]
Once it sings,
we're gonna add
a little bit of pastis
in there.
Pastis?
Pastis is a liqueur
from the south of France.
It's made with star anise.
I think that's like
liquid fennel. Mmm!
Oh, that's awesome.
Yeah? Okay.
Clam broth.
Get a good hand
of pasta.
All right.
So, we sauté all that.
Ah!
So, a little pinch chive,
a little tarragon,
bell-pepper flakes.
We're ready to eat.
Look at that.
The sauce
has all combined
around that beautiful,
squid-ink pasta.
Mother, father,
that's good.
It's good?
The calamari is so tender.
All of these
little components,
just that little bit
of chili flake at the end --
The tarragon, the parsley,
the chive coming in.
What do you think?
That's fantastic.
You like that? Very good.
Fantastic, my friend.
Nice job.
Squid-ink pasta
con calamari.
It's wonderful.
I love the squid ink because
it's different, for one thing.
FIERI: And when we come back,
more different...
We're gonna do
a beef cheek manicotti.
...with a deeper look
into the French-Italian
playbook.
Sacré bleu.
FIERI:
We're at Torinos' @ Home,
where Maxime and Daniela Bouneuo
are serving up authentic,
northern Italian dishes
you'd find in New York City,
San Francisco,
maybe even Chicago,
but not necessarily
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
People come, and they're,
"Where's your meatball?
"Where's your Alfredo?"
And some people
would just leave,
say, "No,
you're not Italian."
WOMAN:
To have the food from Italy,
where I've never been,
is nice,
because I feel like I'm actually
getting to enjoy it
and enjoy the atmosphere
and the ambiance.
FIERI:
And some down-home recipes
you'd be hard-pressed to find
anywhere outside of Italy.
We have a beef cheek manicotti
right here.
WOMAN:
It's absolutely scrumptious
and just melts in your mouth.
What are we into now?
So, we're searing
beef cheeks.
We're gonna do
a beef cheek manicotti.
Butter in the pan.
Everything's better
with butter.
This is the French part
coming out.
Beef cheeks.
Beef cheeks are the bomb!
Little salt,
little pepper.
So they're nice and seared
on both sides, okay?
Lay them
in our braising pan.
Gorgeous.
Next step is deglazing our pan
with red wine.
Get all that fat
off the bottom of it.
Gonna reduce the wine down
a little bit.
In the meantime,
we're gonna start sautéing
our vegetable over there.
Starting with onions,
little garlic,
carrots, and the celery,
just to sweat all that
a little bit, okay?
Gonna put that
on top of our cheeks.
Gorgeous.
And add a little tomato paste
here and there.
We're gonna add our flour.
All that red wine
goes in there.
Cover it
with a veal stock.
Veal stock is done
from veal bone.
We use femur and knuckles.
Roast them?
Okay. Wrap it in foil,
and how long in the oven?
5 hours.
At?
500 degrees.
So, this is out of the oven.
Cools down a little bit
so you can handle it.
So, we're gonna shred.
See? Just like you would shred
for a pulled-pork sandwich.
So, we're gonna add
ricotta.
Sprinkle some Parmesan cheese
in there.
Bring a little bit of salt,
some pepper.
Now we're gonna make
some more pasta.
Again with the semolina,
again with the 00.
We're just not gonna add
the squid ink.
Exactly.
We rolled our pasta.
Okay.
And now we're gonna blanch it
in our boiling water.
Do you see the level
of attention to detail --
just the way he takes the time
to do all of this?
Then what we want to do
is shove them in ice water.
Okay, so now you need
to spread that out a little bit.
Next we take
our cooked pasta.
We take our filling.
We pipe a large chunk of filling
in the center...
Holy schnike!
...and we roll.
There we go!
Like a sushi chef,
the way he's rocking this.
Little Béchamel
in the bottom.
More Béchamel on top.
Little bit of the braising juice
and some of the cheese mix.
We put Fontina cheese,
and we put Pecorino Romano.
In the oven how long?
About 10 minutes.
All right, so,
it cooks in the oven
and then finishes
in the salamander?
Mm-hmm. Here we go.
Our little mix of herbs.
Mm-hmm.
Pepper, garlic oil.
For everybody at home,
this right here --
This is danger,
Will Robinson.
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna take this
for a walk around the block.
I'm not gonna burn myself.
I'm learning.
So that worked, huh?
This is an awesome combination
of the French richness...
Mm-hmm.
...and the Italian rustic.
Decadent.
It's simple.
It's no filler,
all thriller.
Too legit to quit.
I don't know how he does it,
but it's amazing.
I could sell my soul for this.
[ Chuckles ]
So, the people that come here
know it's the real deal.
Is it the real deal?
Yes!       Yes!
Yes!                        Yes!
There you go.
FIERI: Coming up...
This is it, you guys.
...we're headed
to Portland, Oregon...
Get out.
[ Both laugh ]
...for authentic
Chinese noodles...
...made by the master.
That guy's got a gun!
I'm here on Northeast Broadway
in Portland, Oregon,
just a few minutes
from downtown.
Now, this is a pretty busy
street.
Matter of fact, my fraternity
brother Pete that lives here
says he's been up and down
this street a million times
and never stopped
to check this joint out.
That's too bad, 'cause I hear
that they are doing
the real-deal,
off-the-hook noodles!
This is Frank's Noodle House.
Even better than anything
I've tasted in Asia.
Won ton soup, sir?
MAN:
Just authentic and fresh.
When I'm in the neighborhood,
I always stop by.
FIERI: And, of course,
now that I'm here,
Pete decides to show up.
That's Pete.
[ Laughs ]
These are my goddaughters,
this is Ella and Sophia,
and his gorgeous wife,
Laura.
Girls,
what do you think?
It's great.
They make all the noodles
and all the won tons themselves.
I didn't know that.
Yes.
FIERI: The same way Frank Fong's
mother and grandmother did.
Where's your family from
in China?
Northwestern part
of China,
the city called Lanzhao.
Lando?
Lanzhao.
MAN: He brings his culture,
and he brings
his love of cooking
into each and every dish.
FIERI: And when he opened
the Noodle House
with his wife Ying
and son Dennis in 2010,
the pasta was front and center.
You know, it's fresh every day.
They do it by hand.
Chicken noodle ready.
The chicken noodle dish
is wonderful.
Today, we cook
handmade noodle with chicken.
Are we gonna make
the noodle?
Yeah.
That's what
I'm looking for.
All-purpose flour.
Yeah.
This is water.
Get out!
[ Both laugh ]
How long
do you knead this for?
One half hour,
by hand.
We could open up a gym.
Just keeps taking it
and folding it over,
just creating
all that gluten.
So it's gonna give it
the elasticity and the chew,
the texture,
to this noodle.
Who gets the punishment
of making the noodle?
Me. Every day.
That guy's got a gun!
[ Laughs ]
How long
do we let this rest?
10 minutes...
then we knead her again.
Let her rest.
10 minutes later,
knead her again.
Let's rest it.
Sure.
Goodbye.
Okay.
[ Whistles ]
Night, night.
This is to [Whistles]
Yeah.
Okay. Olive oil.
FIERI:
And after resting for an hour...
...it's ready to cut.
[ Whistles ]
That big?
Like spaghetti gone wild.
Okay.
This.
Okay?
Fold her.
Fold her again.
Okay.
Oh!
That one's terrible,
Frank.
Now we're gonna make the chicken
for the chicken noodle?
Yeah.
Okay.
Breast.
Yeah. Chicken breast.
A little bit frozen.
Nice and thin. I like that.
Corn starch.
Egg white.
The salt.
Little bit of dashi.
Yeah.
Then you mix up.
And how long
does this marinate?
One hour.
It's like a rocket ship
in Flavortown, baby.
Little bit of oil.
Chicken.
[ Whistles ]
Bye-bye, oil.
Then we use soybean oil.
Little bit of garlic.
Cabbage.
Yeah. Bell pepper.
Celery.
Green bell pepper.
And onion.
Scallions.
Green onions.
Put the chicken in it.
Chinese pepper.
Red chili powder.
Soy sauce.
Look at that!
Hot and fast, baby.
Oh!
Is it terrible?
Yeah, Frank.
This is bad!
I better get this all
away from you.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
This is it, you guys.
You just taste
the nice, fresh vegetables
and these handmade noodles
and the simply marinated
chicken.
Mmm.
Light.
Veggies are still crunchy.
Is it right?
Delicious.
Mmm, mmm.
Mmm.
[ Mumbles ]
Okay.
[ Laughs ]
There's so much good chew,
and the flavor
just fills your mouth.
It's made with love.
That's what I think
of this food.
What do you think?
Now that I've been here,
it's incredibly good.
Are there gonna be more
Frank's Noodle?
Yes.
Good.
I'm buying in
on the franchise.
Sure.
Big hug, okay?
I love this guy.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Muffled ]
The food's so good here,
I'm picking
off of people's plates.
Ridiculous!
Frank's telling me
to do it.
[ Laughter ]