Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
If you don't come here,
you're totally missing it.
...we're digging into
a festival of flavor.
Off the hook.
In San Francisco, California...
Now you're getting taco truck
on me.
...the funky food truck...
You have, like,
mad ninja skills.
...rolling out some Mexican
flair with a Filipino flip.
That's packing
big flavor.
In Wheat Ridge, Colorado...
[ Laughs ]
...the father-and-son joint...
Here.
...Taking cannoli from dessert
to dinner.
Wow. This is great.
Then in Portland, Oregon...
Dude, I have eaten food
all over the world.
...we're feasting on a first
that will blow your mind.
How have I never had
this?
I'll give you a hint.
Recipes straight from Guam.
Outstanding.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in San Francisco
in the "SoMa" District --
"South of Market" --
to look for a food truck.
Now, I hear these guys
are doing a cross between
Filipino
and Latin-American cuisine.
You never know
where they're gonna be,
so you got to check 'em out
on their Website.
And I found them.
This is Señor Sisig.
This is a pork sisig,
fries.
I love the way the pork tastes.
Two chicken California burritos,
please.
Best burrito ever!
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Okay.
I plan my entire day
around it.
I keep coming back 'cause it's
the best food in the city.
FIERI: With a dynamic pedigree
dreamt up by high-school
buddies, owner Evan Kidera...
Pork sisig
with steamed rice.
...and Chef Gil Payumo...
Order for Dave.
Hey, Dave.
...back in 2010,
they started mixing Mexican
with -- get this -- a sour pork
Filipino dish called "sisig."
Originally, it's the pork head,
cheeks, snout.
We do a little cleaner version
with the pork shoulder.
And Gil stayed true to
his grandfather's sisig recipe
for the truck's signature dish.
Two pork sisig tacos.
It's just so good.
All right, man.
Well, give me the low down.
First, we're gonna start off
with the pork shoulder,
sliced up 1/4-inch thin.
We got some soy sauce over here,
some sugarcane vinegar.
It's a little bit different,
a little bit stronger.
Now we got that pineapple juice
just for that sweetness,
incorporates in the meat.
We've got our minced garlic,
some bay leaves,
some white sugar.
Black pepper,
and we've got some salt.
Mix it up a little bit, and
we're just gonna cover it up.
And how long we let this
marinate for?
So, usually overnight.
Charbroiled ahead of time
at the commissary?
Yeah.
All right.
Now where are we at?
We're making our final marinade
for our sisig.
First,
we're gonna take our soy sauce,
lemon juice, red chili flakes,
and some black pepper.
Then we just whisk this
together.
And then we've got our
charbroiled pork right here.
We're just gonna chop this up
into a fine dice.
There we go.
Now you're getting taco truck
on me.
So, once you got that
chopped up,
we're gonna throw it in
our marinade.
Now, that's gonna go
to the flattop?
That's gonna go to the flattop
to reheat it once again
before it gets
into our tacos.
That soy sauce,
I can smell it.
Is that a normal order?
Yeah, for two tacos.
Wow.
[ Food sizzling ]
Put the corn tortillas
on the grill.
We're gonna take
both of our warm tortillas,
place them on our tray
right here.
The sisig goes on
the tortillas.
Now we're going to the cold
table to finish it off,
some diced onions on there,
a little jalapeño,
iceberg lettuce
and cabbage mixture.
We got our cilantro
cream sauce.
And just a little bit more
jalapeños.
And just two limes.
FIERI:
And that's all she wrote?
All she wrote
right there.
So, you really did mix
the two cultures?
Yeah.
Wow!
That pork has got
so much flavor.
Mmm.
Salty, spicy goodness.
Yeah.
I've had a lot of $4 tacos,
not one with that much meat
in it.
Mmm.
That's packing big flavor.
Nice job.
Right on.
Two pork sisig tacos, spicy.
There's just lots of flavors
in it --
the sour, the salty, the spicy.
That nice little
charred barbecue flavor to it.
These are
your pork sisig nachos.
WOMAN:
Filipino food is something
that people are trying to get
acquainted to.
Not many people know about it,
and Señor Sisig
is doing a great job introducing
it to the general public.
FIERI: And this basket
of spicy chicken goodness...
Adobo buffalo wings.
...gives another dose
of Filipino flair.
It's very reminiscent
of what we used to have at home.
Adobo is a Filipino dish?
Yeah, chicken adobo.
Fire it up.
You've got your chicken
drumettes and wings.
Soy sauce.
Sugarcane vinegar?
Sugarcane vinegar.
Garlic. Bay leaves.
Crushed peppercorn.
And some salt?
A little bit of salt,
yeah.
Mix it all up.
How long's
that gonna marinate?
About five hours.
You marinate 'em,
then how are you gonna cook 'em?
So, usually,
I part bake them halfway
just so I don't burn all that
soy sauce in the deep fryer.
Holds in
a lot of that flavor.
And then what kind of sauce
will you put on the outside?
We're going
a double glaze.
We got the olive oil.
Coat that pan up.
Garlic, peppercorn.
You and your bay leaves.
Bay leaves.
Just get
all those flavors out.
Soy sauce.
[ Whistles ]
Sugarcane vinegar.
Got some chipotle peppers.
Ketchup?
Ketchup. Yep.
Honey for the sweetness.
Brown sugar.
Cayenne pepper.
Red-chili flakes.
Worcestershire sauce.
A little salt.
Cook this down
for about 15, 20 minutes,
just so you can get
all those flavors in.
Got a little cornstarch
slurry?
A little slurry
to thicken it up.
That'll help
tighten it up.
Got some water
just to balance it out.
Let that boil,
come together.
We're gonna throw
these shrimp chips in the fryer.
15 seconds, 350 degrees.
And they just...
They're just gonna pop up.
So, once our -- oh.
Oh!
You have, like,
mad ninja skills.
All right.
We got our seasoning right here.
They're still hot,
so it soaks it right up.
All right.
Put these down as a bed
for our wings.
Okay.
Now we're gonna take
our wings.
Nice and crispy.
Take our adobo glaze.
Squirt 'em in there.
Now we're just gonna
toss 'em up.
A little sesame seeds,
finish off with a little green
onion and lemon zest garnish.
There you go.
I can't figure out
the flavor.
All of a sudden,
I got soy sauce,
then I get chipotle.
Then I get a little bit
of the garlic,
and then I get sweet.
Yep.
The wings are cooked
perfectly.
The big wings,
great crust to 'em.
And the shrimp chips
as accompaniment?
Right on.
For sure.
Not too sweet,
not to spicy.
Not Asian,
not Mexican, just...
Señor Sisig.
Yeah. Right on.
Thanks again, my friend.
Adobo buffalo wings.
The glaze on the wings is sweet
and spicy all at the same time.
It's one of the most flavorful
menu items that they have.
You got to run out and get it.
Good looking out.
Right on.
They take care
of business.
For sure.
Watch out
for these characters.
FIERI: Up next...
[ Stammers ]
Not proofed.
...we're headed to
Wheat Ridge, Colorado...
Just so you know,
they do make a big whisk.
...for a prime-time twist
on an Italian dessert.
A dinner cannoli?
Dinner cannoli.
You know, I think
at one time or another,
everybody's had the dream
of taking what they cook at home
and serving it in a restaurant.
You know,
scratch-making everything,
cooking it to order,
serving the public
like you serve your family.
And every once in a while
on "Triple D,"
we run across one of those
joints, like this place here.
In Wheat Ridge, Colorado,
right outside of Denver,
this is A Taste of Home Cooking.
Greek up.
Kind of reminds me of
when I used to eat at
my grandma's house.
Everything here is homemade,
it's fresh, it's delicious.
Reuben coming up.
FIERI: Just what you'd expect
from CIA grad
and food vet Rob Rotella...
7½ on your German
and your Greek.
...a dude that hit his stride
by heading home,
opening up this joint in 2010
with a partner he's got
a long history with.
Your dad started this?
Him and I started this
together.
I came back from Idaho,
and he decided that he was gonna
do this with me.
So, we opened this
together.
FIERI:
Now we got Bob and Rob
turning the family cookbook
into the menu.
It reminds me of
something you get at home.
FIERI: Including this Colorado
take on an Italian dessert.
Dinner cannoli up.
FIERI: Sausage time?
Sausage for the cannolis.
Word.
We're gonna do
some fresh-ground pork.
Okay.
We're gonna do
some good Chianti wine.
And then we've got
some garlic salt.
Onion powder.
Some basil.
[ Whistles ]
Some oregano.
Fresh fennel.
Tons of it.
And red-pepper flakes.
Sweet paprika.
We're gonna put this
on our mixer,
and we're just gonna incorporate
all of our ingredients.
[ Mixer whirs ]
[ Laughs ]
Now that I've mixed
everything up,
I'm gonna cover it
and let it chill for 48 hours.
Roll 'em by hand.
We're gonna put them
on a sheet tray.
Cut them in half, and then
we're gonna part cook them.
We're gonna go ahead and
bake them for about 15 minutes.
Nice sausages.
Thank you.
So, we have dough straight from
the mixer that hasn't proofed.
Straight from the mixer,
has not proofed.
Not proofed?
Not proofed.
[ Stammers ]
[ Laughs ]
You ready?
I'm ready.
Okay. We're gonna do
the sausage, then.
A little jalapeño on top.
Roasted?
They're a roasted
hatch jalapeño.
Then we're gonna put them
on our pan.
Two at a time.
Cook these for 18 to 20 minutes
at 450.
Word.
We're gonna plate
our cannoli now.
Okay.
Some provolone cheese
on there.
And get some marinara, ladle it
right over the top there.
A little Romano cheese.
A little fresh parsley.
[ Italian accent ]
A dinner cannoli?
Dinner cannoli.
Take a look at that.
Mmm.
Wow.
This is great.
There's a little bit of heat
in there.
It's that jalapeño.
What I really like is that the
dough is a little bit more firm.
But you get that with
some of that nice, rustic
tomato sauce on there.
Like a mini calzone.
That and a little glass
of Chianti -- killer.
Italian sausage cannoli.
I was shoveling that in
as fast as I could get it.
Bless his pea-picking heart
doing all this by himself.
He picks the peas, too?!
[ Laughter ]
He does.
What else do you make
yourself?
Everything.
Everything in this restaurant
is from scratch.
The sausage, the chips,
the corned beef.
FIERI:
Not to mention the sauerkraut,
the main ingredient
in this Midwestern favorite.
Kraut burger up.
Oh, I think this one is superb.
Every bite is just an explosion
in your mouth.
Delicious.
What are we into, Chef?
We're gonna make the kraut mix
for our kraut burger.
So, we're adding
our olive oil.
Then we're gonna add garlic
to it.
Sauté this garlic up
a little bit
and get it
nice and brown.
We're going to add
our beef.
We're gonna brown that up.
Then we're gonna add
our chicken stock.
Here's our parsley.
There you go.
And then we're gonna add
our green onions.
Salt.
We're gonna add
our black, crushed pepper.
I didn't know all of this
was ours.
[ Laughs ]
Is that our spatula stirring
our mixture?
[ Chuckling ] Our spatula
stirring our mixture.
Guess what's in next, ladies
and gentlemen -- our cabbage.
We're gonna let this
cook down
for about an hour and a half
to an hour and 45 minutes.
And we let that chill
in the fridge.
All right, Chef.
Let's get it going.
We're going to make the dough
for the kraut burger.
We got a little bench flour
we're gonna put down here.
And we got our dough
that's basically proofed.
And we'll put this down
here.
We're gonna roll
this out.
Then we're gonna cut it
into squares.
Now we have our mixture
of the cooked-down cabbage.
Then we're gonna...
scoop some of this
right into the --
[ Whistles ]
That's my kind of portion,
captain.
Look at the size of this thing,
Paul Bunyan!
Okay. So, then we're just gonna
pinch the ends,
pull it to the center.
All right. So, now we go
to the oven, 450, 18 minutes.
Yep.
We're good to go.
All right. So, we got
our baked kraut burger
along with
some French fries.
We'll take a little olive oil,
a little fresh parsley,
and then our homemade
honey-mustard sauce.
Here.
Mmm.
See, I love cabbage.
I don't know about you,
but I'm a cabbage junkie.
You've done an excellent job
on this.
You get that cabbage
just cooked down super-tender.
It just dissolves
right into the meat.
This dough that you make
is outrageous.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
Delicious.
Just a good, solid, hearty meal.
You're not gonna go away hungry.
My kitchen's clean.
I don't have to cook anymore.
Not a bad tradeoff.
We drive around the country.
We check out these funky joints.
But believe it or not,
I haven't seen this girl
for 25 years.
Peggy Dilishan.
We lived in Ferndale together.
Everybody at home would probably
love to hear
some real great juicy details
of what I was like as a kid
from Peggy,
but Peggy doesn't want
to talk about that!
Oh, yes, I do!
Oh, no, she doesn't!
No, she doesn't!
Thanks for tuning in.
Have a great day.
Goodbye.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
to Portland, Oregon...
You are turnin' and burnin'.
...for a food truck...
Oh!
...serving up
a "Triple D" first.
The bomb-Guam-dot-com.
I'm here
in beautiful Portland, Oregon,
about five minutes east
of downtown
in the Rose City Neighborhood
at the Rose City Food Park.
With these trailers,
you can find
just about anything you want.
You name it.
But one that stands out for sure
is serving up
a type of food that we haven't
seen on "Triple D" before --
Guamanian.
That's right --
recipes straight from Guam.
This is PDX Six Seven One.
The food is amazing.
MAN:
Some shrimp fritters.
I've never had
Guam food before.
FIERI:
Not until Ed Sablan's food cart
became the culinary ambassador
of Guam in 2010.
SABLAN: It's Chamorro food.
Chamorro?
The indigenous people, the
culture of the Mariana islands.
Guam's
the largest southernmost island
of the group of islands.
My absolute favorite is
the kélaguen mannok.
Kélaguen and titiyas.
Cold chicken salad.
It's fantastic.
What are we gonna make
here?
The kélaguen mannok.
"Mannok" means "chicken,"
and then kélaguen is
the way it's prepared.
Chopped, grilled chicken.
Okay.
Let's get into this.
So, what we're gonna do
is take the bone out.
Dude, I got to give you
some props on the technique.
Hey, thanks.
You are turnin'
and burnin'.
What up next?
The marinade.
Chopped onions.
Ground pepper.
Vinegar.
I use cane vinegar.
Cane vinegar.
Soy sauce.
Some water.
How long is this
gonna marinate?
So, we'll cover this,
put it into the fridge,
and then we'll grill it
in the morning.
Awesome.
Okay, hit it.
All right.
What kind of wood
we cooking with?
It's a natural mesquite
charcoal.
We're gonna cook this
all the way through.
I let it sit there
for about 10 minutes,
rearrange,
another 10 minutes.
Flip it over,
So about half an hour.
And so now we're gonna
take the chicken, cut it up.
I got to try this.
Even cold,
the chicken is outrageous.
Green onions.
Got some yellow onions.
Some Thai chili peppers.
So, it does have a little bit
of spice.
Some grated coconut.
Then we're gonna put
some lemon juice,
and it's gonna bring it all
together.
What are we gonna serve it
with?
It's called titiyas,
or coconut-milk flatbread.
Okay.
Flip it over again.
Fan it out.
And there you go --
kélaguen mannok with titiyas.
Oh!
Dude, I have eaten food
all over the world.
Yeah.
How have I never had
this?
That soy kick coming through
the chicken,
a little bit of the spice,
the bread.
You get a touch of that coconut,
the green onions in there,
a little bit of that lemon juice
coming through.
Oh! Mmm!
That's one of the best chicken
salads that you will ever try.
Off the hook.
I mean that.
The bomb-Guam-dot-com.
It's so packed with flavor.
You can imagine a street vendor
on an island out in the Pacific
grilling this up on their grill
and serving it up to you.
FIERI:
And when we come back...
All right, so here are
the shrimp fritters,
boñelos uhang.
U-hang around tonight?
It's more-o of the Chamorro.
The background music
for this should be
some type of Rocky Balboa thing,
man.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: At the Rose City
Food Park in Portland, Oregon,
they've got food trucks
for every type of food.
There's a lot of variety.
And they've got one named after
both the airport
and the area code
that's getting its Guam on.
It's the only place that has
Guamanian food that I know of.
SABLAN: Fried shrimp fritters.
Done.
The shrimp fritters
are very unique.
We're gonna make
our boñelos uhang batter.
Boñelos -- ball?
Uhang -- shrimp.
Oregon pink shrimp,
sustainably raised.
Corn.
Peas and carrots.
Even it out.
A.P. flour.
Salt. Black pepper.
Baking powder.
Got it.
Just enough to coat it
a little bit,
make a little bit
of a binder.
Now we're going to combine
our evaporated milk and eggs.
Milk in a can.
Another big Guam thing?
Yep.
All right.
Throw that in.
Oh, this is my kind
of batter.
Not a bunch of flour.
Look at the ratio
of the ingredients.
We're gonna scoop it out
and drop it in the deep fryer.
Ball 'em up.
Let's roll.
350?
375.
About 30 seconds in,
I'll take tongs
and crack 'em a little
just to make sure that inside
gets nice, light, airy.
Dig it.
All right.
So, here are the shrimp fritters
or boñelos uhang.
I serve it with garlic,
black pepper, vinegar sauce.
Outstanding.
Great crunch.
It's got
great shrimp flavor.
The batter's not heavy.
The peas pop with the vinegar
and the sweetness of the corn.
It's simple, basic,
and dynamite.
The background music for this
should be
some type of Rocky Balboa thing,
man.
[ Laughs ]
[ Humming
"Eye of the Tiger" ]
You are the champion.
This is awesome.
Boñelos uhang, order up.
It's deep-fried,
but it doesn't taste like
that oily deep-fried stuff.
It all stands out in
your mouth, and it's
really, really exciting.
I love to experience part of
the planet that otherwise
I probably won't be able
to visit any time soon.
The best food cart in Portland.
It is such a hidden little gem
you have here.
Out of bounds.
If you don't come here,
you're totally missing it.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
That was funny.
Why was that funny?
'Cause you laughed
in the middle of it.
Well,
what do you want me to do?
It was you looking at me
that way.
[ Laughter ]