So, here I am,
south of the border.
This is "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" in Cabo San Lucas.
First stop...
Tacos!
...the taco shack...
Simple and delicious.
I mean, that's the key.
...doing their take
on the tostada.
Way more than a taco stand,
dude. Way more.
Then, on the marina...
Let's hit it, brother.
...a real-deal seafood joint...
Outstanding, man.
...serving up
some early a.m. classics.
Can't beat it.
Plus, we got a sushi spot...
Fresh fish all the time,
every day.
...just rolling
with the good times.
Outrageous.
It's the sun, the fun,
and even some Sammy.
We in Cabo, baby! Whoo!
That's all right here, right now
on "Triple D" in Cabo.
Now, as you can see,
the '68 didn't make it.
A little issue
getting across the border.
But don't worry about that.
It's a perfect time
to drive the Baja racecar.
So, I've been coming to Cabo
for a long time,
and everybody's been telling me,
for the best tacos,
you got to check this joint out.
And in the land of tacos,
that says a lot.
This is Asi y Asado.
WOMAN:
I have pork and arrachera.
Best food in town,
in my opinion.
One arrachera taco.
Can't beat the tacos here.
What makes Asi y Asado
so great?
The tortilla and the salsa.
That has to be perfect.
FIERI: And perfection for owner
and chef Gustavo Jimenez
comes from doing things
just one way.
We make handmade tortillas.
FIERI:
You make the tortilla?
Yep.
Along with everything else since
he opened this stand in '06.
Everything is fresh.
We have scallops,
shrimp, fish, octopus.
[ Needle scratches ]
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Octopus?
Two orders, octopus.
Yeah, the octopus taco
is really good.
And we're gonna make octopus
today?
How do you say it
in Spanish?
Pulpo.
Taco de pulpo.
Look at the size of that.
We got it
just out from the sea.
And how are
we gonna prepare it?
We have to boil it
a little bit,
and then we drop
to the charcoal.
Just add salt, pepper.
Bay leaves.
An onion.
And a little bit of orange.
So,
we just drop the octopus
in boiling water
for half-hour.
And what are we gonna serve
with this?
What kind of salsa?
The pico de gallo salsa.
You make the chips?
Yes, sir.
This is
the handmade tortilla.
You just put it
on the grill.
You didn't fry them?
No, sir.
This is healthy stuff.
Awesome.
And it's crispier than any chip
you'll ever try.
Pico de gallo.
Just onion and lime.
And what makes
really good pico de gallo?
The secret is
the lime cooks the onion.
Really?
You do it first.
Crushed tomatoes.
Cilantro, Serrano pepper.
It's hot. Be careful.
A little bit of salt.
And let this sit
for a little bit?
Yeah,
just a couple minutes.
So, that's ready.
So, we got some skewers in
the water so they don't burn up.
The pulpo is cooled down.
We just take
a couple tentacles.
Chop it. Chunks.
Small chunks.
That's it? And then
you just throw it on a skewer?
Yes.
That's it.
On the grill?
Off to the grill.
And what kind of wood?
...from the mountain.
From the mountain?
Yep.
Got it.
I like the tortilla press.
Yeah. This a gift
from my grandmother.
We do like 40 kilos every day
times seven years.
Really?
Can you imagine how many
tortillas this press made?
Just this press?
Just this press, yep.
You have to do by hand.
Just put it there.
Just press
a little bit.
Do it again
because it's not equal.
So, when you turn it the other
way, you get an even press?
You got to basically do it
twice.
And this is a corn tortilla.
Three minutes to cook.
We can...
Beautiful tortilla.
You make your own masa?
Yep.
That's the secret, buddy.
We start with the skewer.
Just take like this.
Put some pico on there.
Mmm. The octopus is so fresh,
it tastes like the sea.
It's got texture.
The pico de gallo
really is nice.
The handmade tortilla,
it's fresh, it's moist.
Simple and delicious.
I mean, that's the key.
And the rule is less is more,
you know.
Less is more.
Outstanding.
You can taste the octopus.
It has a very nice flavor.
It's not, like, chewy.
It's, like, crunchy
because it's grilled.
Delicious. One of the best ones
here in Cabo.
You come to Cabo,
you will be happy.
Because it's a paradise.
You just come here
and you live like on vacation.
FIERI: And what better way
to top off a day at the beach?
[ Bell rings ]
Tacos!
And you just never who's gonna
show up to get some.
One of my favorite bands,
Rage Against the Machine.
This is my buddy Brad Wilk,
the drummer from Rage.
Tell me about
the taco experience here.
This is the best place
to come down and eat tacos.
They just make them
right here.
Go figure. I wonder why.
[ Both laugh ]
Always gonna be delicious,
always gonna be fresh.
So, like, if you don't like
seafood, they also have pork.
Vampiro.
I got the Vampiro, which is
a tostada with some pork on it,
some of the pineapple salsa
that they have here,
which is excellent.
Now we're going to make
the pineapple salsa
for the pork chop Vampiro.
We just need some oil.
And then some green onions
is the key --
The small ones,
not the big ones.
Not the big ones.
A little salt, pepper.
Plum sauce.
Like Chinese plum sauce?
Yeah.
Seriously?
Do you use plum sauce
in Mexican cooking a lot?
No.
No, this is like a fusion.
This is you going crazy.
Yeah.
Pineapple jelly.
Sriracha sauce, and then we have
the pineapple juice.
And then some fresh pineapple,
as well.
So, let this cook down.
20 minutes.
Now, we're gonna blend
the big chunks,
because we just want
the flavor.
The sabor.
Huh?
I think your Spanish
is better than my English.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
Pineapple juice.
Yep.
The lid.
This is the same, but it's just
small pieces so you can bite it.
So, this continues to cook
a little bit longer?
About 20 minutes,
yes, sir, it is.
Outstanding. Delicious.
So, we got the pineapple salsa
cooked down, reduced,
and now it's cool.
Now we're gonna make
the Vampiro.
Okay.
We have
the corn shell tortilla.
What kind of cheese?
Monterey.
Monterey Jack?
Yeah.
The pork chop.
Here, the pork chop is the loin
without the bone.
It's on top of the taco.
You can taste the sweet
and the salty from the pork.
Mmm.
You know what it tastes like?
A really thin crust
Hawaiian pineapple pizza.
The saltiness of the pork,
the sweet and the sour
from the pineapple.
What do you call it?
Vampiro.
What does that mean?
Vampire.
Vampire?
Yeah.
As many times
as I've been to Mexico,
I have never had Vampiro.
Outstanding.
Glad you like it.
You're the man. Way more
than a taco stand, dude.
Way more.
It's a good taste,
the combination.
The salsa is one of the best
salsas I ever have tried.
It's very, very fresh, sweet.
It's delicious.
I love it on just about anything
that I order here.
Pretty funky joint,
but the tacos are of the best?
They are. They're great.
[ Laughs ]
This is the taco spot.
I'm done.
My job here is done.
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
to the marina...
Light it up.
...for the perfect
front-row seat
to the freshest catch
of the day.
Real typical dish you see
in Mexico all the time.
So, if you've ever been
to Cabo San Lucas before,
this looks familiar.
It's the marina. All kinds of
shops, all kinds of restaurants.
This is
where you go fishing from.
Now, the place that I'm taking
you to, I've been there before.
If you're looking for some
real-deal food and a great view,
you got to check out
Solomon's Landing.
MAN: You'll love the food,
you'll love the atmosphere,
everything about the place.
MAN #2: Spectacular views,
very romantic.
And the food, well,
as you can see, is to die for.
FIERI: And you can thank
owner Brian Solomon for that,
a California ex-pat
who ditched the corporate life
to buy this former taco stand
back in '95.
Over the years,
Brian's transformed the taquería
into a laid-back, outdoor oasis.
He goes all out.
He just caters to his customers.
FIERI: And he really wins them
over with this fresh catch.
Stuffed fish.
Straight out of San Lucas Bay.
Tantalizes the taste buds.
FIERI:
So, what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
the lobster sauce.
So, we got everything --
mirepoix, shrimp shells,
lobster shells, lobster claws,
you name it.
It's all in here.
Got it.
So,
that's been roasted off.
Now we're gonna put some butter
into there.
Now we're gonna put
a little brandy in here.
There you go.
Flour there.
And we're just gonna
cook it down a little bit.
Now the water.
How long are we gonna let this
cook down for?
Probably about 20 minutes.
Add a little roux to there to
thicken it up a little bit more.
Shrimp base to give it
a little bit more depth.
Okay.
A little bit of tomato puree
to give it some color.
Reduce this down.
Strain it off.
So, now we have
the lobster reduction done.
Did you catch the fish?
Actually, I did not, but he was
a happy camper yesterday.
So this is that fresh?
Really?
This is actually what they call
a true red snapper.
In Spanish,
they call huachinango.
There's the filets.
Basically, you dip it
in whole-egg batter.
Panko it.
Then put it in clarified butter
on the grill.
Char them up
Now we're gonna make
the finishing sauce
that's gonna go on top
of the fish.
Correct.
A little olive oil,
a little garlic.
I'm gonna add
tomatoes, onions,
mushrooms,
and some white wine.
Real typical dish you see
in Mexico all the time.
Now we're gonna add
the lobster sauce.
Marinara.
And heavy cream.
So, let this reduce down
a little bit,
and then this will go
on top of the fish.
Yeah.
Plate it up.
Okay.
Cilantro risotto.
Another piece.
And now the little sucker
that brings it all to life.
And there.
We're ready to eat.
First, I got to say,
you could put the lobster sauce
on a flip-flop...
...and it would taste good.
I mean, literally.
The risotto,
with that cilantro,
is nice, bright, fresh,
clean flavor.
The richness of the lobster
is outrageous.
Good one. Really nice.
Excellent.
Thank you very much.
Your delicious stuffed fish.
It's always flaky.
I know it's fresh.
We get
the freshest seafood here.
It's three or four hours
from ocean to plate.
FIERI: And you just can't beat
watching the sun rise
while chowing down on
this classic Mexican breakfast.
WAITER:
A dish of chilaquiles.
If you want real chilaquiles,
this is the place to come?
Yes.
All right, Chef,
now, what are we into?
We're making the red sauce
with chilaquiles.
So, stewed-down tomatoes,
onions, peppers, garlic?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
That's it.
Put some olive oil
in there.
Almost get
to where it's smoking.
We're gonna actually scorch it
in the very beginning.
The first part goes in there.
Really want to have
that scorched flavor.
A little pan juice
in there.
Now we're gonna add a little bit
of chicken base
and salt and pepper.
Let that cook down
just a little bit longer,
and then I'm gonna add
the tomato sauce in there
to give it some color.
What's next?
What we're gonna do
is take a sauté pan.
We're gonna pour the sauce
we just made into there.
Boiled chicken.
We're gonna add
the cilantro.
In with the tortillas.
Fried tortilla chips.
Nice, big, thick tortillas.
Now we're going to
start plating.
This is fresh cheese
actually made here in the Baja
they call farmer's cheese.
Take a little heat
off the palate.
Red onions, and then some sour
cream, and a sprig of cilantro.
Sprig?
That's like a garden.
Now, I have had
a lot of chilaquiles.
You want them to get
a little bit soggy
but still have texture
in the tortilla.
A little bit of heat
in that.
The texture's great,
the flavor's great,
the spice isn't too much.
A little sour cream, a little
farmer's cheese in there.
You'll get a dip
of the guacamole.
Mmm.
What I love about it, Chef,
is just
all the little components
that you take
that extra step with,
and it really makes
a real deal.
Awesome.
Outstanding, man.
Best chilaquiles I ever tried,
not even at home.
Sorry, Mom.
When we come back,
Chef has got a hangover delight.
Killer stuffed French toast.
See you in a little bit.
"Triple D" in Cabo San Lucas.
Welcome back.
"Triple D"
going international,
across the border,
Cabo San Lucas.
And we're hanging out
at Solomon's Landing.
Now, we have tried
fantastic chilaquiles.
We've also tried
what they call a stuffed fish.
This,
this is supposed to be,
from what I've heard
from everybody around here,
the hangover cure of all time.
Stuffed French toast.
After some tough nights in Cabo,
it'll help you a little bit
with your hangover.
What are we into?
This is the compote
for the stuffed French toast.
Starting out
with a little whole butter,
fresh strawberries,
bananas.
Raw sugar.
Frozen strawberry compote.
Now we're gonna add
a little brandy
to really bind these flavors
really good.
Next up?
A nice, big pullman loaf.
You bake it?
We have a bakery
that bakes it for us.
Okay.
We're just gonna slice
a couple pieces off of here.
Now we're going to put
some cream cheese on both sides
so we can stuff it.
Now we're gonna stuff it
with the fresh strawberries.
We try to use
a local product.
A lot of the year, we're able
to get local-grown strawberries.
Now we're gonna go in
for some bananas.
Okay.
Now we're gonna
push it together.
Let's hit it, brother.
Now, what's in our batter
over here?
Eggs, milk,
cinnamon, nutmeg, cream?
And brandy.
Compote with the brandy.
Beautiful.
I'm not a huge breakfast fan,
but I do appreciate
good French toast.
A little bit of sweet,
a lot of fruit.
Some banana.
Really nice.
No need for any syrup.
The juice from the compote
itself is just great.
Can't beat it.
Well, thank you.
Can't beat it. Delicious.
It's unbelievable.
I tell them
we can never make it at home.
Good food, good price,
good people.
I love this place.
Nice job, Chef.
Well done.
Thank you very much.
FIERI: Up next...
I'm picking up
what you're laying down.
...the sushi spot...
I like where that starts.
...rocking out
the deep-fried fusion flavors.
That guy's a surgeon.
So, on my final leg
of this "Triple D" tour
of Cabo San Lucas,
I found myself
back at the marina,
not too far
from Solomon's Landing.
I'm here to check out a joint
that my buddy Gorilla --
You remember Gorilla Rich from
Gorilla Barbeque in Pacifica --
He says he's been to this place
a bunch of times.
It's off the hook.
This is Tiki Bar.
Fish tacos are ready.
This is our local spot
to come to.
It's in kind of
a touristy area.
Locals and tourists,
we mix and mingle well.
It's right here on the marina.
I love the food, everything.
FIERI: Just the kind of place
owner Moises Gonzalez
was looking for
after he became a local in 2005.
A place for people to come in,
hang out.
Couldn't find a place like home
in Cali.
Really?
And to make it feel
more like home for the locals,
chef Manuel Aradando is taking
advantage of the surroundings.
I know it's fresh 'cause if I
didn't catch it, my friends did.
So, fresh fish all the time,
every day?
Every day.
The sushi is excellent here.
That's right --
sushi in a Mexican joint.
It's fresh.
You can't fake that.
From the classic rolls
like the rainbow and spider
to the turducken of sushi.
Heavy nagasaki.
Layers of fresh fish inside
a butterflied shrimp roll
drizzled
with homemade eel sauce.
You see it every day.
We're gonna prepare today
the heavy nagasaki.
So, what we're gonna do
is start with this surimi salad.
And this is imitation crab.
Imitation crab.
We're gonna add
a little bit of mayonnaise.
The masago.
That is the...
Fish eggs.
...fish eggs.
Add the togarashi.
Japanese peppers,
with a little bit
of sesame seeds
and orange zest.
And last but not least,
the Sriracha.
So, then what we're gonna do
is just mix it up a little bit.
Try it.
I like where that starts.
I don't know why you got to do
anything else to it.
This tastes great.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna take
our Pacific blue shrimp.
We are going to butterfly it,
and then we do one more.
So once and then twice?
That's correct.
Then we're gonna go ahead
and do our salad.
Okay.
Next, we're gonna do
a piece of salmon.
That guy's a surgeon.
There we go.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
Then we fold it, and we wrap it
in nori, the seaweed.
I'm picking up
what you're laying down.
These are beautiful.
Then our tempura,
and then bread crumbs.
Fold it in tempura like this.
Then the bread.
All good to go.
Okay.
So, the next thing,
we're gonna fry.
And we're gonna serve it
with the eel sauce.
A little rose. Very nice.
Mango sauce.
And then more eel sauce.
Finish it off
with a little red sesame seeds,
and we have
some microgreens.
Gorgeous plate.
Okay.
The way you treat the shrimp
and the tenderness
of that shrimp is outrageous.
Outrageous.
Although it was fried,
it doesn't have a real heavy
fried taste to it.
It's very light.
The salad has just enough
of the Sriracha.
A little hint
of the salmon.
This is outstanding.
Thank you.
Oh!
Heavy nagasaki up.
Super-crispy
and really delicious.
MAN #3: We're at the southern
tip of the Baja Peninsula
where the fishing
is the greatest in the world.
So it's the freshest
in town.
I love this restaurant.
I come here every day,
ever since he's had it.
Just bring people here.
It's a wonderful spot.
I'm just like you guys. I mean,
you go somewhere, you're like,
"Where should I go eat?"
A funky little place -- small --
and these guys do it legit.
We got to do more sushi
on "Triple D."
So, that's it for this edition
of the "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" Cabo tour.
Now, before you leave, there's
one joint you got to check out.
It's not about the food.
It's all about the rock.
This is the Cabo Wabo Cantina.
[ Rock music playing ]
I hope Sammy's in the house.
Yeah! Sammy Hagar!
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives,"
we in Cabo, baby! Whoo!
[ Laughter ]
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives,"
all of them.
"Triple D."
In Cabo. Yes!
There's your outtakes.
[ Laughter, applause ]