Hey, everybody!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Get ready. Get your jaws going.
It's on.
...it's the spicy
New Mexican combo...
All of your mouth
lights up.
...of sandwiches and stew.
It's kind of oddball.
I know.
Yes.
In sunny Albuquerque...
My mouth is already starting
to water.
...the seven-table
warehouse spot...
When I say funky joint,
I mean funky joint.
...plating up
chili-inspired creations...
I couldn't shovel that
in my face fast enough, could I?
...for the whole dang town.
YNIGUEZ:
So, I feed a thousand kids
before 10:00 in the morning.
A thousand?!
And north in Santa Fe...
Ready to do this,
man?
...the African joint...
No matter what he's making,
it sounds good.
...serving up savory keepers...
♪ Row, row,
row your goat ♪
...straight out of Kenya.
If that's the only dish
you sold,
I'd come back every week.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"!
So, I'm here in the older part
of Albuquerque, New Mexico,
known as North Valley.
Now, out here,
you'll find everything
from horse ranches
to organic farms,
but more importantly,
got a cool, little restaurant
where the chef owner started
by selling burritos
out of the back of her car.
Now she's got
a little take-out restaurant
where she's making --
get this --
over a thousand meals a day
for local schools.
This is Bocadillos.
How long on a T&A, sir?
It's real people
making real food
that real people want to eat.
YNIGUEZ:
After that, a Philly.
It's fresh. Love it.
They're good people, friendly.
Gonna be a busy day.
FIERI: And for owner and chef
Marie Yniguez, that's every day.
Since '09,
this Albuquerque native
has been delivering the goods
on what the locals crave.
We love chili in New Mexico.
We put it on everything.
FIERI: And they're a staple
of Bocadillos' sandwiches.
Not only does it taste good,
but it makes the whole
neighborhood smell good.
FIERI: So, I'm gonna follow
my nose down the road,
where Marie's cousin Charlie is
rockin' his Hatch-chili stand.
FIERI: So, let me
get this straight.
This right here is
the Hatch chili?
Yes, it comes from Hatch,
absolutely.
So Hatch is a place?
Yes, chili capital
of the world.
Let's turn her on.
Now, that's my kind of machine.
Only takes eight minutes
to roast these babies
to perfection.
My mouth is already starting
to water.
It smells so killer.
I've never seen
a chili-roasting stand.
Welcome to New Mexico.
Yeah,
welcome to New Mexico.
There we are.
Look at that!
And we're gonna cook with this?
Yes, sir.
In fact,
they're the crowning glory
on one of Marie's top sellers...
T&A on wheat.
FIERI: ...a New Mexican spin
on the turkey sandwich.
It's extremely flavorful.
It's legit.
We're gonna start
with the dry rub
for the turkey
for the T&A sandwich.
The T&A?
T&A.
What does T&A
stand for?
Turkey and avocado.
We got crushed peppers,
garlic, salt, pepper,
a little bit
of brown sugar.
Mix all this up
together.
Dry rub goes on?
Dry rub goes on.
Not on the inside?
No, I like it
to fall apart
as soon as I pull it
out of the oven.
And what is
this concoction?
So, that right there is
our house-made honey mustard.
Just go ahead
and toss it on.
Good to go.
Pretty.
Wrap it up in foil,
stick it in the oven
for 12 hours at 250.
All right,
roasted turkey.
Pretty much when you take it
out of the oven,
it just falls apart.
That honey mustard...
rocks the house.
It's pretty sick, huh?
We're gonna make
the green-chili apple chutney.
So, this is typical
chili peeling in New Mexico.
But you're wearing gloves?
Oh, yeah.
Because...
'Cause you don't know
if you're gonna touch your face
or anything else later.
Ready to go.
And then, basically,
you just...
Nice roasted flavor,
not super spicy,
but those will all range
in heat, right?
Yes.
And this chili apple chutney's
gonna go on the turkey?
Yes.
You get your diced apples.
A little bit of sugar.
So, about a cup and a half
of chilies.
Let it all
just cook down.
And then you'll start getting
the sweet and the hot,
and you'll be ready
to go.
So, we're gonna put it
in a hoagie roll.
Whole wheat?!
Yep.
You have a little healthy
somewhere in there.
[ Laughs ]
So, you put your green-chili
apple chutney,
let it soak into the turkey,
and that's kind of what makes
your whole sandwich.
Got the Muenster cheese
going.
As in Herman?
As in.
So, we got the green-chili
chutney going.
Here we go.
Is that a serious portion
or what?
That's a serious portion.
We do about 8 ounces
per sandwich.
Heirloom tomatoes fresh
from one of the gardens
here in the valley,
avocado.
There you go --
your very own T&A.
That's what she gave me,
okay?
That's a sandwich.
No, that's a dinner
for six.
What do you think, yeah?
The sweet and the heat
with the roasted turkey
and the mustard --
I don't know
where you came up with the idea.
It's delicious,
and the little burn
of the chili in the back...
It's just the love.
It is the love.
Carley,
you have a T&A sandwich ready.
The turkey's moist.
The bread is awesome.
It has all the chilies in it,
which is really good.
It's enough for two people.
That's for sure.
FIERI:
Marie just wants to feed you,
a skill she's taken
way beyond this tiny restaurant.
What are you doing
for all these hours?
I mean,
there are seven tables.
Well, because we feed
charter schools.
So I feed a thousand kids
before 10:00 in the morning.
A thousand?!
A thousand.
I'm here for my community.
I'm here for New Mexico.
I'm here to feed the future,
and we do it all from scratch
just the way my mom and my
grandma taught me how to do it.
All right,
what are we making next?
We're gonna do
the Reuben.
Get ready. Get your jaws going.
It's on.
Duke City Reubens are
my favorite.
WOMAN:
The meat is so tender.
It's a wonderful, hot sandwich
with plenty in it...
FIERI: starting with
a spiced-up corn beef.
Okay,
so, juniper, clove...
Bay leaf.
A little coriander.
We got a little bit
of cinnamon
and a little bit
of red peppers.
Can you smell it?
I gotcha.
All right, so,
basically,
we just put our pickling spice
right on top,
get it rubbed in a little bit,
get it ready to go,
put a little bit of salt,
pepper.
A little bit of garlic.
Rub it all together.
So, put it in 12 hours.
In the oven 12 hours?
Mm-hmm.
Duke City Reuben.
Yeah.
Dun-dun-dun!
There you go.
Smell's the part.
So, you let it cook down
to where it
just completely shreds.
We're not slicing this
at all.
No, not at all.
There you go.
Try it out.
Mmm!
What do you think, yeah?
I'd eat that all day.
I couldn't shovel that
in my face fast enough, could I?
And now we make
the sandwich.
Yes, sir.
Let's be respectful
of what a real 8-ounce is.
You almost killed me
last time.
Corn beef, little bit
of our homemade sauerkraut.
Put that right on top.
Put a couple of pieces
of Swiss.
House-made Thousand.
And is there chilies
in this?
It's a little bit
of chipotle.
[ Sizzling ]
Clear the landing pad.
Check her out.
Give her a taste.
I got a lot of corn beef.
I know it's hard
to tell.
[ Record scratches ]
It's tender,
not too salty.
The dressing is
gangster.
Thank you.
Love the cabbage.
A little toast on the bread --
great crunch.
That'll rock your lunch.
Duke City Reuben's
super delicious.
It is just so juicy.
The food is amazing.
I shouldn't have to eat
until tomorrow. [ Laughs ]
We're hanging out
at Bocadillos
in Albuquerque,
New Mexico.
So, when we come back,
what are we gonna make?
Biscuits and gravy.
See you in a bit.
I'm hanging out
at a funky joint.
When I say funky joint,
I mean funky joint.
We're, like, in a warehouse
in Albuquerque, New Mexico,
and this is Bocadillos.
The chef over here,
she feeds a thousand kids
lunch and breakfast
and then opens
her restaurant
to serve people
off of seven tables outside.
Did I get that right?
That's exactly right.
And now we're gonna get into
exactly what you expect to find
in the middle of the heat
of Albuquerque, New Mexico.
We're gonna make...
Biscuits and gravy.
Right. Hit it.
Start with...
All-purpose flour?
...all purpose flour.
Baking powder rolling in,
butter all cubed up,
and a little bit of salt.
People come here
and get biscuits and gravy?
They do, actually,
when it has great chili in it.
Regular milk.
I just use whole milk.
Get yourself
your ball of dough.
When are we gonna
put the green chilies in?
We'll put it
in the gravy.
And when do you sell
green-chili gravy biscuits?
All day long.
We do it for the kids,
too.
This is one thing that we do
for the kids for breakfast.
Kids love the biscuits.
Yep.
So, you're gonna
roll this out.
Roll it out.
You make biscuits every day?
Oh, yeah.
[ Chuckles ]
Now, these are gonna go in
the oven. What temp? How long?
350 for about 20 minutes.
What are we doing?
We making the gravy?
We're gonna make the gravy
right now, right now.
All right, let's do it.
First, you're gonna get
your pork all ground.
Now, why aren't we going
to the pot?
Because I like to put it
on the flat
and then drain it
a little bit.
You got your pork
all ground up.
You can add it
to your pot.
[ Sizzling ]
You got your milk.
Pepper.
Garlic.
Oregano.
Crushed red pepper.
Where's the flour?
I don't have any flour.
I thicken it
with corn starch.
You do it with slurry?
Yeah.
It's kind of oddball.
I know.
And you got
your green chili.
Whisk it all up,
get it going.
So, thicken with corn starch
soon as it comes to a boil,
and you got gravy.
And that goes
over the biscuits.
That goes
End o' story.
[ Whistles ]
Fully-cooked biscuits.
Nice, big, and fluffy.
Wow.
Kind of like me.
So [laughs]
Just cut them in half.
I'm gonna butter
both sides.
Put the hash browns
on the bottom.
Kind of brown them a little bit
just like that.
Gonna get your gravy.
Smother.
I'll just put your egg
on the side, Guy.
You got red chili flake,
green chilies.
Mm-hmm.
Sausage.
I mean,
here's what you got.
Hand-made biscuits and gravy,
some hash browns, an egg,
some green chilies,
a little bit of spice.
This isn't your regular --
This isn't your grandma's gravy.
Let me just tell you
that much.
If I knew I could drive
down the street,
get this for $4.50, $6,50,
$7.50, I wouldn't care.
You scratch-made it.
You scratch-making everything.
Mm-hmm.
That's the beauty.
Yeah, it's the only way
I know how to cook.
You're gonna get good quality
every time you come.
Every time I come here,
I get something different.
I love this place.
You're priceless, girl.
I'm gonna tell you something.
You really are priceless.
You -- You give a lot
to people,
and it comes out
in your food.
You're the bomb.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
You can do it.
Yeah, man. Yeah, man.
...we're headed to Santa Fe...
Good times, right?
...for an authentic taste...
If you're missing
a goat,
might be right here
in the bucket.
Well, that's possible.
...of -- you got it --
Kenyan classics.
So, I'm here in beautiful
Santa Fe, New Mexico,
enjoying
exactly what you'd expect --
phenomenal weather,
chili peppers,
wonderful artists.
Then you got to think about
the African/Caribbean cuisine,
and then you've got the adobe --
[ Record scratches ]
Oh, you don't know about
the African/Caribbean cuisine,
I mean, with the roti
and the goat stew?
Oh, probably 'cause you haven't
been to this joint, Jambo Café.
Coming right up.
There you go.
Jambo Café is cloud nine for me.
One order of mahimahi.
Very authentic.
It's a very unique style.
Goat stew with the roti.
MAN: It reminds me
of exactly what I would have
if I was back in Kenya.
FIERI: Flavors that owner
and chef Ahmed Obo missed
from the place he was raised --
the island of Lamu
off the Kenyan coast.
After all these years
of me back home cooking,
this town has nothing like this.
FIERI: After working stateside
in other restaurants,
including "Triple D" alum
Zia Diner...
Bok choy.
I'm waiting for bok choy.
FIERI: ...he laid down roots
in his own joint...
Chicken curry.
There it is.
FIERI: ...with a focus
on fresher-than-fresh flavors
that come together
in this present of a dish.
Mahimahi's ready!
I get mahimahi
at a lot of restaurants,
but this one is different --
the texture and the taste.
I really love it.
Chef, what is a dude
in Santa Fe, New Mexico,
doing with a big, gigantic,
fresh mahi?
You know,
I'm from the island,
so I need,
you know, like...
Fresh fish.
...fresh fish.
Let's make some fish.
OBO: There we go.
Now you're in it.
There we go.
So, we're gonna cook this
with the skin on
or the skin off?
We're gonna take
the skin off.
We're gonna rub it with spices
from back home.
FIERI:
What are we starting with?
So, we have fresh ginger.
Chili powder
and have thyme.
FIERI:
Island food and thyme.
There you go.
Then we have coriander,
get our spice.
Another favorite --
garlic.
This is garlic.
And then we have
a cinnamon.
This is jalapeño.
Jalapeños?
Yeah, we grow some chilies
back home.
And black pepper.
Some black pepper goes in there.
Put some bok choy in there.
Okay.
Paprika to give it, you know,
the redness in there.
Yeah.
Okay.
The redness.
Yeah.
Let's get this guy going.
Got to combine together.
The oil.
So, a nice, wet rub
almost like a baste.
I'd put that
on a flip-flop.
I got the fish
right here.
Okay.
Then just put in there.
Look at that.
How long is it gonna stay
on there
before we cook the fish?
Overnight, so that way,
it sinks right in, you know?
Okay, brother,
now what are we on to?
Coconut tamarind
mango sauce.
Right, so, we got yellow onions
right here --
goes into the pot.
Garlic.
Okay.
Curry powder.
Smells good already.
And a little bit of oil.
Cumin, got cayenne.
Coriander.
Got it.
Ginger and thyme.
And the thyme.
Feel the magic.
Feel the burn.
Once the spice starts to stick
to the bottom,
that's when we want
to throw in some mango.
Island mango, fresh,
you know, just out of the tree.
I actually picked it.
There you go. We're gonna pour
this coconut milk in there.
And is this the tamarind paste
already diluted?
Yes.
Kind of got a sourness
to it.
Pour it right in there.
Awesome.
There you go.
[ Train horn whistles ]
All of your mouth
lights up.
I can see the light
in your face, man.
So, we're gonna go
to the salt.
You know what that is?
Vinegar.
There you go.
Okay, so,
now we got that done.
You're gonna wrap the fish
in the banana leaf.
This was kind of like
natural plastic wrap --
retain the moisture and
add a little bit of flavor.
So, then I'm gonna go
this way.
Then I'm gonna go seal it.
Gonna do a strip?
I love to do the strip
'cause it reminds me
of back home.
So, there's my --
Like, you did this
700,000 times.
Now you go to the steamer.
How long?
About 15 minute.
Ready to do this, man?
Let's do it.
And so,
there's your mahimahi.
Cut it.
There's your fish.
Have a black rice here.
Okay.
And then we're gonna go
and put the fish,
then we sauté baby bok choy,
then here's the sauce
that we made.
You just put it
right over it.
He's so mellow.
Sprinkle parsley.
Get one lemon.
Put it right on the top.
The island spice
banana-leaf wrap.
Okay,
the fresh-caught mahimahi.
Mmm.
Wow, that's tender.
The fish can't be
any more fresh.
Serves it with the black rice,
the fresh veggies.
Mmm.
The tamarind mango sauce.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
Very soulful dish.
Everything is good.
Thank you.
This guy.
Mahimahi's ready!
Really fresh, really tender,
nice and moist.
It's beautiful, as well.
FIERI:
And Ahmed's made the restaurant
just as good-looking.
The artwork actually moves you
to Africa.
It's like a little vacation
when you come in.
We're hanging out
at Jambo,
African/Caribbean cuisine
in Santa Fe, New Mexico.
I know,
the home of the chilies,
but Chef Ahmed is gonna
make us...
Some Caribbean goat stew.
See you in a bit.
FIERI: Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Santa Fe, New Mexico,
and, no, we're not doing
a joint
that's serving up
the awesome chilies.
We're doing a joint
that's serving up the awesome
African/Caribbean cuisine.
So, now
what are we gonna make?
We have, you know, the goat,
so we're gonna do goat stew.
If you're missing
a goat,
might be right here
in the bucket.
Well, that's possible.
[ Both laugh ]
So, anyway, we're gonna start
by, you know, curry.
Okay.
Curry powder.
Then I'm gonna do cayenne,
all spice in.
Coriander.
This is coriander.
Then our cumin,
and I use a lot of the spice
all over again.
Ginger?
Ginger, ginger powder.
A lot of dry rub.
And then get cinnamon.
That much?
Yeah.
Salt now, so I'm gonna sprinkle
all over.
Then I want to mix it up
a little bit here, yeah.
Underneath. Come on.
Dig deep. You can do it.
Yeah, man. Yeah, man.
Yeah, man.
Now, how long will it stay
with the dry rub on it?
A few days,
all the spices sinking in.
You should smell it.
It's like a spice market
right now.
Next up?
I got a blended olive oil.
It's not too thick.
So, there it goes.
And then from there --
So, this is
one whole goat?
This is one whole goat.
So we're talking
goat front,
goat back,
goat middle...
Goat back, goat middle.
...goat tenderloin,
goat rib...
Everything.
...goat shoulder.
Just grab this paddle
again.
So, now, everybody at home,
together with me...
♪ Row, row,
row your goat ♪
You'll be singing it
tomorrow.
So, we're gonna sit there
and stir that up.
Gonna sit.
Let it sear a little bit
on both sides.
Yeah.
Now what goes in?
We're gonna put
the onions.
Add garlic.
Now we need to dump in
the tomato paste
a little at a time,
man.
We're gonna add a little bit
of beef stock first.
And then
what's this other one?
That one is chicken.
A little fat
on top of there.
That's why we need
to add the fat
'cause, you know,
the goat's...
The goat's very lean.
...a little lean.
So, we bring it to a boil,
and then from here,
we're gonna slide it into
the oven for about 2 1/2 hours.
All right, so, now you put
the carrots in, potatoes.
And then from there,
we just mix it up together.
Got it.
So, there is your --
Look at that!
There is your goat.
Look at that.
Then on the roti,
a little bit of oil.
Nice.
[ Chuckles ]
You got to be kidding me.
That goat is
so tender...
and so...rich.
And you get the roti.
Yeah.
There you go.
Huh?
Yeah.
This right here
is about as real deal --
If that's the only dish
you sold,
I'd come back every week.
It's outstanding.
The goat stew
with roti.
WOMAN: It's unlike
anything I've had before,
as if the spices
are really of the earth.
MAN:
The goat stew reminds me
of exactly what they prepare
in Kenya.
Lamb burger with cumin fries.
I love the Jambo Café.
MAN: It gives me
a homemade feel to it
every time I come here.
It's the best.
You'll love Santa Fe,
and you'll really love this guy.
This is the bomb.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"!
You know
you're saying it right now.
You're saying, "Row, row,
row your goat."
Just wait.
Can't say, "Row, row,
row your chicken.
Row, row,
row your beef."
[ Laughs ]