Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Vocalizing ]
FIERI:
...we get a little comfort
and a whole lot of soul...
Which is a big difference.
...in Kansas City, Missouri.
This is the place!
The barbecue blues joint
going full speed...
This has got trouble in
turn four written all over it.
...with a NASCAR legend.
Man, he's lapping you.
[ Laughs ]
In Portland, Oregon,
the funky Tin Shed...
This is exactly
what I came here for.
...rocking out
real-deal vegetarian.
I'd eat that
till my head fell off.
Awesome.
And in Albuquerque,
New Mexico...
To the fryer, then.
...the microbrew restaurant
dishing out
the New Mexican soul.
That's mandatory
right there.
Mandatory delicious.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here
in Kansas City, Missouri.
[ Engine revving ]
Now, most folks --
Most folks would argue
this is like the epicenter
[ Revving continues ]
of great barbecue.
So I'm here to check out
a joint...
[ Engine revs ]
...that has been smoking
the meat and rocking the blues
for over 20 years.
This --
Geez, what is this?!
Hey, city boy!
What do you know
about barbecue?
This is Clint Bowyer,
and this
is B.B.'s Lawnside BBQ.
You're killing me.
King combo.
Kansas City is the barbecue
capital of the world...
Burnt end dinner?
MAN: ...and B.B.'s is the best
barbecue in Kansas City.
Barbecue sundaes.
It's an authentic
Kansas City experience.
A little blues,
a little brews,
and some great barbecues.
FIERI: A killer combo
that local blues radio host,
Lindsay Shannon,
had a hard time finding.
If you look around town,
there are not very many places
doing blues and barbecue.
So in 1990, he and his wife, Jo,
resurrected this old roadhouse,
and 15 years later,
handed the kitchen
over to Mike Nickle.
Got rib tips
coming out hot.
But, as Clint and I
are finding out,
the real star here
is the 1950s hickory smoke pit.
Can you crack that for us?
Let's see what this looks like.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Ooh!
Look at that.
All right,
so what are we gonna make first?
Well, we're gonna prepare
a whole brisket,
and we're gonna prepare it
for burnt ends.
Are you a burnt ends fan?
Oh, Yes.
Oh, I love burnt ends.
You can't come to Kansas City
without having burnt ends.
Bring it.
It's Kansas City, baby.
All right, so give us a rundown.
What do you got?
We're gonna start with
just making our brisket rub.
Seasoning salt,
meat tenderizer.
Give it a good mix here.
We're not gonna be shy.
We're gonna be real generous
with the rub.
Rub it in.
We're going straight
to the smoker.
12 to 14 hours.
[ Vocalizing ]
Next up, we're making
our B.B.'s mild house sauce.
Why are we doing mild?
What's the difference
between the mild and the hot?
Just the cayenne pepper.
Which is
a big difference.
Okay, so get the cayenne.
We're gonna go big.
Bowyer wants to make hot sauce.
We're making hot sauce.
All right, let's start out
with some ketchup.
That's
a lot of ketchup.
Apple juice.
Next, we're gonna go
with vinegar.
Then we're gonna go
molasses.
White sugar.
White sugar
and brown sugar.
Celery seed.
Ground clove.
Yeah.
Cinnamon.
So, you got the cayenne?
Yeah, here we go.
All right.
Now we're gonna go one more
just for Clint.
Oh, extra hot.
Whisk it together.
What happens
when you're in the race suit,
and you had extra hot
the day before?
It's bad.
All right,
how long is this gonna simmer?
This is gonna simmer
for an hour and a half.
Next up,
brisket with smoked.
Point was cut.
Cooked it down
two more hours.
Now this is gonna give us
the burnt ends.
Let's take a look.
Ohh!
I got to just grab some
with my hands.
That one's mine.
Yours is still in there.
Way in the back to the left.
Go get it.
Look at that.
Perfection.
Time to cut.
Now, we're just trimming off
a little bit of the --
A little bit of the fat
that's still left on there.
Now we're
just gonna cut it
into the chunks
we all know and love.
Look at that.
You don't get that
in California.
Look at that "nobule"
of meat.
Is that food talk?
This is a winner
right here.
Oh, daddy.
That is money.
Now, here comes
the hot sauce.
Oh, the double cayenne
delight.
The brisket
is just tender, pull-apart.
Mm.
Oh.
Now, a lot of times,
people think about
Kansas City barbecue sauce
being super tomato-y.
This is my kind of mix.
Good vinegar,
a little kick of that molasses.
The heat's not too
over the top,
but the key
is the tenderness.
Look at this smoke ring
right here.
It just falls apart.
It's perfect.
Burnt end dinner.
MAN:
This is a real burnt end.
As good as you'll find
in Kansas City.
Absolutely.
They are delicious.
Now that I can't eat
anymore --
I know he can.
He's got to race on Sunday.
Matter of fact.
But when we come back,
we are gonna try
some more fantastic barbecue.
We're here
at B.B.'s Lawnside BBQ.
See you in a minute.
Welcome back,
"Triple D" hanging out here
at B.B.'s Lawnside BBQ.
In Kansas City, Missouri.
And that's Clint Bowyer.
You know him from NASCAR.
Listen, Chef Mike
has been rocking the house
on some awesome barbecue.
I don't want to eat any more.
I don't want to eat --
but please,
what are you going to make?
We're going to make
our barbecue sundae.
[ Dramatically ]
Sundae, sundae, sundae.
Must be race day.
Race day.
We're gonna make
a Boston butt.
What are we
gonna season it with?
The 1,000-year-old pit
does all the seasoning for us.
And what we're gonna do is,
when we pull it back out,
we re-season the pork.
No seasoning, no salt,
no pepper, no nada?
No nothing.
In the smoker 12 hours,
no seasoning.
This I got to see.
Let's do it.
Here we go.
What are we into now?
Well, we're gonna make
our pork seasoning.
Now we're gonna season
the pork?
Yes.
We're gonna start out
with seasoning salt.
We are gonna add brown sugar,
white sugar, and black pepper.
All right.
12-something-plus hours.
See, when you can wiggle
that bone out like that...
That is on time
right there, baby.
I'll get you some bling.
Have that all done up.
Yeah, that'd make
a nice necklace.
Now what we're gonna do
is we're just gonna simply
pull the pork.
See that nice bark
and smoke line
and good richness
in there.
You know, it is unbelievable
the flavor that's in that.
Pork by itself
has great flavor,
with all that fat
and the bone being close to it.
Let me just taste
a little bit.
I want to see what's gonna
happen with this rub.
So, you're just gonna take it
and give it a little sprinkle?
Mm-hmm.
Can Clint do the sprinkling?
Yeah.
Go ahead, Clint.
Thank you.
Just one good handful,
don't be shy.
Now we're ready
to build the sundae.
We're gonna start out
with our pit beans.
Next, we're gonna add
our coleslaw.
You ever see
anything like this?
No. Never.
Pulled pork,
and top that
with a dill pickle spear,
a little bit of sauce.
And that's
our barbecue sundae, guys.
Bottoms up.
So, the beans --
Not super sweet.
Everything's kind of soft,
but the crunch of the slaw
really comes through.
And then you get
that smoky pork on top.
You're still
on the first layer.
Man, he's lapping you.
[ Laughs ]
That's good, brother.
Excellent job, man.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
WOMAN:
You scoop it out of your jar,
and then you've got your
three-course meal right here.
It's a true
barbecue lover's meal
where you just kind of dump
everything together
and it's all mashed up.
WOMAN:
There's so many good restaurants
in Kansas City for barbecue,
but B.B.'s really pulls it all
together with the atmosphere.
FIERI: And with a cannot-resist
fan favorite of Clint's
starting in the pole position.
Order of battered fries.
It's not really a French fry,
and it's not a baked potato.
It's just something different
and unique.
All right,
so what are we gonna make?
We're doing
battered fries.
Yes, trust me.
"Trust me"?
Show us how it's done, son.
Starts out,
we cut a raw potato.
What kind of potato?
Idaho.
Right into our fryer
for five minutes.
Then we're gonna take 'em out,
let 'em cool,
and then start
the dredging process.
All right.
We're gonna start out
with some flour, black pepper.
Seasoning salt.
What we're gonna do is just
whisk that together really well.
Okay.
And now for the batter.
We add milk.
Add the eggs.
Give 'em a quick whisk.
Now we're gonna add
seasoning salt and black pepper.
Give that
a quick little whisk.
Now comes the fun part.
Now we're gonna cover
our cooked potatoes.
So you dredge 'em into the wet,
back into the flour,
and now we're good to go,
and these are battered fries?
Yes.
Now we're gonna go
straight into our fryer.
How long?
Now, those are gonna take
a minute and a half.
90 seconds.
Look at that.
I'm a ketchup guy.
Are you, really?
Let's eat, Mr. Ketchup.
Hmm? Hmm?
Hey...
if a fry isn't good enough
as it is,
let's coat it
in something.
I'm telling you,
this is the place!
When Clint Bowyer
throws down a karate chop
to a stainless-steel table,
you know it's the place.
Battered fries.
Let me get a picture of this.
Here, hold these.
[ Chuckles ]
There we go.
Nice!
Brother, thank you so much.
We're out.
Hey, thank you guys.
[ Laughs ]
City boy lost his keys again.
Now, how does he say it?
It's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up...
How is that gonna survive
on a flat top?
...we're headed
to Portland, Oregon,
for some off-the-hook dishes
that are leaving me speechless.
He likes this one.
[ Laughs ]
You think you can tell?
I can tell.
I'm here in the Alberta Arts
District of Portland, Oregon,
to check out a joint
that's serving up
some of my favorite
kind of food.
No, it's not barbecue.
Not Italian.
Not Mexican.
It's not Chinese.
Nope, it's a type of food that
my sister taught me to love.
You got it -- vegetarian.
And I hear they're rocking it
right here
at the Tin Shed Garden Café.
I love this restaurant.
KADEN:
The baby beluga up!
It's a staple on Alberta.
You're under a rock if you
don't know about Tin Shed.
Yes.
Exactly.
Dill pickle mac and cheese.
The food is unique.
The flavors are unique.
FIERI:
Heck, even the story's unique.
'Cause while owners
Janette Kaden
and Christie Griffin
had waited a lot of tables...
You had never
been a chef...
Never.
...nor cooked
at a restaurant.
Correct.
Never.
And you just figured,
you would --
Start a restaurant.
FIERI:
And more than a decade later,
their brand of comfort food's
a big hit
with Portlanders looking
for some tasty alternatives
like this cleverly named
sandwich.
The heartless artichoke.
I grew up meat and potatoes.
I'm eating
an artichoke heart sandwich.
It's fantastic.
What are we making?
We're gonna start by making
the artichoke mix.
So, these are...
Marinated.
...artichoke hearts.
Chopped.
Yep.
Lots and lots of Parmesan.
A fair amount of garlic.
Mayonnaise.
A little lemon juice.
Some crusty salt.
Crusty salt.
A little black pepper.
And some sugar.
Love sugar.
How is that gonna survive
on a flat top?
Okay, hit it.
Okay. A little oil.
So, you're gonna think
this is crazy.
We're just warming it
through,
and it's gonna stick
to the grill.
Roasted red peppers.
So, we're gonna take
this sourdough bread
and then
some clarified butter,
and we'll throw that down.
Wow.
Pepper jack cheese.
Like a vegetarian
Philly cheesesteak.
Like so.
Yummy coleslaw.
He likes this one.
[ Laughs ]
You think you can tell?
I can tell.
What wouldn't you love
about that?
I love artichoke hearts,
especially marinated ones.
Creamy, hot.
Pretty wide spectrum of flavor
from the cheese side of it
to the roasted red bell pepper
side of it.
Great sourdough bread with
a little bit of crust to it.
I'd eat that
till my head fell off.
Awesome.
MAN:
It's perfect, you know?
You couldn't get
a better sandwich.
But before you go thinking
this place
is just about veggies,
think again.
I wouldn't call it
a heavily vegetarian place.
I think it's just good food.
This is a little bit
of something for everybody.
Yes.
Including your dog.
[ Dogs barking ]
That's right, even Fido and Fifi
can get their eat on.
And while the canines are
chowing down on chicken and rice
and ground beef
and sweet potatoes,
here's something their owners
are gonna dig.
The baby beluga.
It's a kind of dish
that you eat,
and you just feel
really good after.
What are we gonna make next?
We're gonna make baby beluga,
which is a curry lentil dish.
[ Whistles ]
And we're gonna start
with the curry.
What's it called?
Baby beluga.
It's not caviar.
It's black beluga lentils.
We're just gonna start
with some coconut milk.
Some yellow curry paste.
Madras curry.
So we do this powder
in the paste?
Yeah.
And we'll cook that down?
Yes.
Curry sauce is done.
Now we're gonna make
the lentils?
Exactly.
A little olive oil.
Welcome
to the cornucopia.
What is this,
the garden here?
Yellow onion
and then
a little roasted sweet potato.
Beluga lentils.
Roasted mushrooms.
Roasted garlic.
A little kale.
I love kale.
Look at that.
And then this is the curry sauce
that we made earlier
going right on in there
till it gets nice and saucy.
Throw some fresh spinach
and some jasmine rice,
and the curried
veggie lentil goodness.
A little bit of peanut
and a little bit of sweet
from the raisin
and a little bit of creamy
texture from the avocado.
That's a very important part
of this dish.
I mean, I don't even know
where to start with this.
You have to get avocado
in that bite.
It's rich,
variety of textures.
Complex.
Especially when you get
that little kick
of the roasted garlic there,
and then you get a crunch
or just a little bit
of the texture of the lentil,
and then you get
the sweet potato coming through.
And then you get the earthiness
of the kale.
I mean, there's just all these
complexities going on there.
And the creaminess
of the avocado.
This is the kind of dish,
and I'm not kidding you,
that my sister, Morgan,
would love so much.
This would be the kind of dish
she would see
and just go,
"You found it."
Yeah, right.
This is awesome.
The baby beluga up!
I think I'm gonna get this
every single day from now on.
Isn't it dynamite?
This is amazing.
It's a concept
I wasn't ready for.
It's in your face, man.
It's great.
Fungus among us!
This is exactly
what I came here for,
to show people
that this is the kind of food
that you also find
in Flavortown.
You rock.
Nice job.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
Spock grip, huh?
...we're headed
to Albuquerque, New Mexico...
Very nice.
...for a southwest turn
on some classic soul.
[ As Scotty ]
Captain, I'm giving you
all the power I can.
So, here I am
about 10 minutes north
of downtown
Albuquerque, New Mexico,
right off the I-25
in a big industrial area
that's packed with --
Wait for it.
No, wait for it.
Exactly what you're thinking.
Micro breweries, a bunch of 'em.
But we're here to see
one in particular.
This joint.
Nexus Brewery & Restaurant.
Here's the pork sliders.
The food is excellent.
FIERI:
From the chicken and waffles...
and fish and chips...
to the soul burger.
Really, really good.
FIERI: Most people, though,
didn't start coming here to eat.
MAN: I came to this place
for four or five months
before I even tried the food
'cause I liked the beer so much.
And in the last couple months,
I've really become a big fan
of their food.
FIERI: 'Cause Albuquerque native
Ken Carson...
Where are we on the waffle?
...is mixing
some homegrown flavor
into family dishes
from the South.
We do what I call
New Mexican soul food.
It's a combination
of Southern cooking
with New Mexican cooking.
Very nice.
Like green chili
in the mac and cheese...
homemade pico
on the chicken gumbo...
and a little extra kick
mixed in with this dish.
Chicken fried chicken,
Rayna.
I didn't want to stop eating.
It's so good.
All right,
what are we gonna make first?
Okay, we're gonna make the brine
for the chicken.
Start off with our water.
I'll just pour it on in.
Instead of using regular salt,
we decide to use seasoned salt
to add a little extra flavor.
Sugar.
Equal parts of sugar and salt
basically, got it.
Chopped garlic.
And then finally,
we have our two chopped onions
right here.
Okay, so the brine's made,
chicken goes in.
How long is the chicken
gonna be in there?
We're gonna be in there
for 24 hours.
Next, we're gonna do
the egg wash.
All righty.
It starts off
with our eggs,
then we use
Frank's hot sauce.
I like that.
A little on the spicier side,
that takes it.
A little bit of water.
Stir that up.
Okay.
So then we take
our brine chicken in the flour.
And into the flour.
Do you season that flour
at all?
Just a little bit
of salt and pepper.
Do you make these
ahead of time?
How does the process
normally go?
Typically,
we just do 'em to order.
Right like this?
Right.
To the fryer, then.
And that's it.
Fry 'em off?
Correct.
About 10 minutes...
Be good to go?
...and we're ready. Yeah
First thing's first.
Collard greens.
What go in
your collard greens?
Onions, we do some bacon,
then we put in
some red chili pods
to add a little bit of spice
to that.
Mashed potatoes on.
Then our gravy.
And what's
in the gravy, boss?
Shallots, cream,
black pepper.
Typical things
for a Southern gravy.
I mean,
that is some crispy chicken.
There's a ton of crunch,
but it's not --
The breading's
not too heavy.
And even though you had
all that hot sauce in there,
it's not spicy.
It's just really flavorful.
Nice mashed potatoes,
good, crunchy chicken,
a lot of flavor.
And my favorite
out of all of 'em is the greens,
which I can't believe
I'm finding collard greens
in New Mexico.
That's mandatory
right there.
Mandatory delicious.
What do you think of it?
It's really crispy
and tasty.
Moist on the inside,
crunchy on the outside. Perfect.
Trying to watch my weight,
but I can't help myself.
It's funny that they call it
the Nexus
because it's the point
where you get
the joining
of the food of this quality,
and you are getting beer
the likes of which
you are not going to be able
to find anywhere else.
FIERI: And while that's
a great analogy,
it's not quite
how the joint got its title.
Where'd you come up
with the name "Nexus"?
From "Star Trek."
Seriously?
I used to love "Star Trek"
when I was a kid.
[ As Captain Kirk ]
James T. Kirk.
[ As Scotty ]
Captain, I'm giving you
all the power I can!
Spock grip, huh?
Scratch-made beer,
soul food under the same roof?
That's love.
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We go plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughter ]