Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Out of bounds.
...I think I found the answer.
If something makes you young,
it's jambalaya.
The trio of soup, salad,
and seafood.
This will make you happy,
man.
In Franklin, Tennessee...
You got a little twang,
you know.
I'm throwing twang in it!
You're doing good.
...the Double Cinco...
Just a little
something-something.
...tossing up
outrageous oysters...
Look at that!
...and a fiery
fried-chicken sandwich.
I'm not gonna fit
in my swimsuit.
In Kansas City, Missouri...
You should smell it,
by the way.
...a down-home comfort joint...
That's
my campaign message.
...where the name
just says it all.
You name yourself PotPie,
you better deliver.
Then in Nashville...
Here we go.
Coming at you.
...the funky café...
It's medicinal.
Medieval is more like it.
...where eating well
means eating well.
You eat good, then
you can eat naughty, too.
That's a hell of a way
to put it, girl.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm about 15 minutes south
of downtown Nashville.
But more importantly, I'm only
like an hour north of Lynchburg.
You know, the home
of the world-famous
Jack Daniel's distillery.
Come on.
Anyhow, I'm in Franklin,
Tennessee,
to check out a joint
that the people in the know
say I got to see.
This is 55 South.
Pork Chop Sandwich.
There's no better place to be.
Everything is perfect.
Hot Chicken, bag of shrimp.
Food is amazing.
It's different.
It's fresh. It's tasty.
McCONNELL:
BLT in the window.
Plenty of variety. That's what
makes it really good.
FIERI: And all part
of Jason McConnell's
personal roadmap,
a poli-sci grad turned off
by D.C. politics
and turned on
by southern cooking.
And in 2010, it all became part
of the 55 South menu.
It's a little bit of everything.
Cajun, it's country, it's a
little bit of Memphis, Franklin.
FIERI: Even a local dish
I like to get when I'm in town.
The Hot Chicken.
The Hot Chicken knocks it
out of the park.
It'll set you on fire.
What are we
gonna make first?
We are going to make
Hot Chicken marinade.
Marinade.
You got a little twang,
you know.
I'm throwing twang in it!
You're doing good.
We got a little paprika.
It's the base, 'cause
you want to have red chicken.
We got salt, black pepper,
Louisiana hot sauce, cayenne.
[ Whistles ]
Granulated garlic.
A little oil.
You want to get this
kind of going.
Got a little bit of water.
This is paste.
This is spackle.
That's the napalm.
If you can't afford
pepper spray,
just carry a handful of it
when you walk down a dark alley.
Look at that look.
It's not that bad.
Awesome.
We're gonna marinate
and finish the chicken sandwich
with this.
We're gonna save
just a little bit.
We'll put the chicken
in this.
Old Ranger Danger over here
took the chicken breasts
and gave it a little score.
You know, just --
[ Squelch! ] -- sucked it up.
Just gonna get
the paste on it.
How long would you really
like to let this marinate?
A couple of days.
Now we're gonna make
the dredge.
We got some flour
with a little baking powder
in it.
Granulated garlic.
A little paprika.
We really want to get
some color in that.
Cayenne.
Creole seasoning.
More salt.
Okay.
Kind of an all-purpose
Cajun dredge.
And then we got
our atomic chicken.
We got the oil.
Got the oil.
We're just gonna lay
that in.
No dropping these
into a fryer.
No, you got to go
with the skillet. 375.
Three to five minutes?
Yeah.
The key here is that score
to that breast.
That's where you let
the funkalicious get in there.
We're good. Okay.
So, we're gonna do
a little white bread.
White bread.
Little mayo.
A little schmear.
Two pieces.
Two?
I'm not gonna fit
in my swimsuit.
A breast, a breast.
You're gonna put more
of that on there?
Enough already.
That's the way you normally
make it for people?
Yeah,
it's the perfect amount.
This is a key component.
You got to have
lots of pickles.
And always, you know,
you got to give it the --
bring it all together.
A lot more
than I bargained for.
Just a little
something-something.
Here we go.
Not hot.
I have any here?
Not here or here,
but, like, right here.
A little.
Little bit?
You're good.
The chicken
is super tender.
There's great crunch, nice
texture on the outside of it.
Not overly done
with batter.
The pickles
are the only thing
that are gonna save
your life.
Chef, awesome job.
Definitely spicy.
JEFF: Slightly peppery,
good crunch,
the texture, flavor --
This has got it all.
Outstanding.
This gentleman right here
is Lori Arnett's husband.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, he also happens to be
Jeff Arnett,
master distiller
of Jack Daniel's.
FIERI: And libations
are just one thing
that anchors folks
to this place.
MAN: I love cold drinks,
and 55 South provides me
with something cold to drink.
It's kind of a Cajun Cheers,
I guess.
Cheers.
[ Laughter ]
Well, you can get
just about anything here.
FIERI: Including fresh seafood
up and down the menu.
Tuna nachos up.
Shrimp what?
Shrimp in a Bag.
Best oysters in town are here.
You have served
over 1,000,000 oysters
since 2010?
Well over a million.
That's a lot of oysters.
It's a lot.
I'm having
the char-grilled oysters.
It's oysters with cheese
and goodness and wholesomeness
and all kinds of other
good stuff in there.
So, we're gonna make
some char-grilled oysters.
We're gonna shuck
some oysters.
And you're bringing what type
of oyster in?
Gulf oysters.
I'll just put this in.
[ Pop ]
Got it.
There you go.
Keep the liquor.
We're gonna do our cheese,
parmesan-reggiano,
grated mozzarella,
chopped Italian parsley,
fresh-squeezed lemon juice,
a little lemon zest,
a little Creole.
Stir this bad boy up.
And then we're going on top.
We don't want
to be shy with it.
Really?
So, this is kind of like
Oysters Rockefeller
just turned into
a grilled cheese sandwich.
Exactly.
I like the way you roll.
It's Tennessee oysters.
Now where do they go?
Wood-fire grill.
Creole combo.
We'll get a little melt
on the cheese.
Splash of the butter.
Tray on top.
So, we got oysters
coming off.
And we're gonna take a little
bit of our garlic butter,
and we're gonna finish
these guys.
Little bread.
Look at that!
Dip that in a little bit
of that juice,
piece of that bread.
The wood-smoke component
to it is out of bounds.
That's what knocks it
over the top.
Mmm.
My friend, delicious.
Char-grilled oyster up.
MAN: The butter, the cheese,
the garlic melts in your mouth.
It's just wonderful.
They're perfect.
Don't worry.
The party's not over.
Although it looks like
we're getting smoked out
of the joint.
When we come back
to 55 South,
Chef and I are going
to make...
Jambalaya.
Out of bounds.
See you in a minute.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Franklin, Tennessee,
at 55 South,
'cause that's where...
That's where
the magic happens.
the magic happens!
I'm still sweating
after the chicken sandwich
that we had.
Keeps you young.
If something makes you young,
it's jambalaya.
This is real deal.
I'm just telling you.
So, what do we --
In your jambalaya --
Mine, I like to do pork butt,
chicken thighs,
smoked sausage,
holy trinity.
I mean,
I go the whole gamut.
Is that where we're going?
Chicken and andouille.
We make the andouille here.
You make the sausage?
We do.
Of course you do.
The mise is ready.
First thing --
you got a hot pan over here,
put some blended oil in.
Chicken.
This is breast.
We're gonna get that going
just for a second.
Got some celery.
Bell pepper, onion,
a little garlic.
Loving it.
Let that go for a second.
Really just kind of breaking up
the chicken in there
a little bit.
I gotcha.
We're gonna cut up
some of this andouille.
Look at that.
So, we got the sausage
going in.
I like the way
this looks, man.
We're gonna do
some dry thyme,
basil, oregano,
chopped Italian parsley.
Hot sauce.
Louisiana hot sauce.
Creole.
I like where
you're going with it.
And then we're gonna do
our liquids.
Tomato juice.
Chicken stock.
Little bit
of crushed tomato.
Got a little simmer
going on.
We're gonna add
some long-grain rice.
And now you can't leave
till it's over.
We're just gonna
let that simmer
until all the rice absorbs
the liquid, and that's it.
If you got to make any phone
calls, check your e-mails,
I can watch the pot
for a bit.
Looks awesome.
Good color, lot of product,
lot of sausage.
And a little extra hot sauce
on the top.
Some fresh scallions.
That's it.
That's all she wrote.
What we have here
is real-deal jambalaya.
Not too spicy.
The really nice piece
is the andouille.
Great smoke
coming out of that.
But that's the little element
that pushes it over the top.
It just makes
all the difference.
The rice is tender.
Little scallion
on the outside.
Nice, round heat coming
from that Cajun seasoning
and the spices you put in.
This will make you happy,
man.
My friend.
Chicken and sausage jambalaya.
It's so good.
LORI: It's not too spicy.
It's just perfect.
It's good to know
that we won't have to just
travel down to New Orleans now
to enjoy some good jambalaya.
You see?
FIERI: Coming up...
Look at that thing.
...we're headed
to Kansas City, Missouri...
Put the rest
of this magic together.
...for the perfect ingredient
in pot pie.
The juju.
Put the juju in there.
So, if I'm in Chicago,
what do you expect?
Exactly. Hot dogs.
San Diego? Fish tacos.
New Orleans -- po' boys.
North Carolina -- pulled pork.
You get the idea.
So here I am midtown
Kansas City, Missouri.
What do you expect?
You got it.
This is PotPie.
Pot pie.
MAN: Pot pie is classic.
Kansas City comfort food.
Exactly.
WILLIAMS:
I got three pies going.
It's my buddy Steve Post
with MRN Radio.
This dude's legit. What do
you think of the pot pie?
This is absolutely amazing.
See?
Okay, Sarah, I got a pasta
and a pie ready to go.
MAN:
Their menu is so simple.
They just tend to execute it
very well.
MAN #2: There's a lot
of attention to detail.
It's inventive
without being pretentious.
FIERI:
The same way you'd describe
French-trained chef and owner
John Williams.
We follow standard, you know,
French technique.
You Frenchified
comfort food.
Sure.
And when he opened this joint
in 2003,
the name was an afterthought.
We didn't even have pot pies
the first few months we opened.
Seriously?
What makes
righteous pot pie?
Good juju.
You put the good energy into it
when you make it,
and that's what they get
when they eat it.
That juju's working its magic
in two versions --
one with beef and mushrooms,
the other -- braised chicken.
Chicken pot pie.
Very hot tonight.
It's the best version
of a comfort food.
All right, man.
Get it going.
Okay.
Fresh chicken.
I'll season it,
salt and pepper.
Our pan is plenty hot.
Sear it off
skin side down like that,
try to get
a nice, good color.
Searing this off is the first
step in building flavor.
Rendering the fat.
I dig it.
We'll pull them out.
Okay.
Onions, celery, carrots.
A little mirepoix.
Yep.
We add garlic.
Sweat it good.
Now we'll return the chicken
to the pot.
Got it.
Hot chicken stock.
That's been on
since yesterday afternoon.
Wow.
Cook that overnight.
How long
we gonna let this go?
This will go
for about an hour.
Cover it with tinfoil.
You should smell it,
by the way.
Ooh.
In the oven how long?
For about an hour.
Bring it out.
Strain it?
Yeah, lay it out,
cool it down.
Pick it. Pick it.
For the filling,
what are we doing?
We're gonna start
by getting our broth going
with mirepoix -- onions,
celery, carrots, garlic.
Wow.
And leeks.
Leeks, I think,
are the key.
I don't think people
use enough leeks in general.
It really adds that depth.
That's
my campaign message.
Two leeks in every pot.
Like it.
I'll get on board.
So, we got
the mirepoix going.
Got good color on it.
And we're gonna go ahead
and add some chicken stock.
So, this is coming
to a boil.
Season it
with salt and pepper.
Thyme.
Ooh.
Lots of thyme for this.
Now I'm gonna add my roux.
This is the flour
and the fat.
We'll whisk that smooth.
We've got the roux
incorporated.
We add a little bit of corn
right at the end.
Now all we got to do
is assemble them.
Okay. Put the rest
of this magic together.
This is our picked chicken.
Put a goodly amount,
but not too much.
Ladle the broth over.
Just give me
a bowl of that.
This is puff pastry.
Got it.
Salt and pepper on top.
That's it? In the oven?
How long?
About 10 minutes.
Oh!
See the steam coming out.
That's a definite sign
that it's ready.
Look at that thing.
Half a chicken in there
practically.
Mmm.
It's creamy.
There's enough pastry
to it.
Nice veggies.
The flavor's really deep.
Delicious.
Brother,
I'm gonna tell you this.
You name yourself PotPie,
which we've never seen
in the history of "Triple D,"
you better deliver.
And you delivered, man.
Mmm.
The juju.
Put the juju in there.
The inside of it
is fantastic.
I mean, the meat
and all the stuff in it.
But this crust on the outside
is so incredible.
Something you definitely want
to eat on a winter's day.
Just down-home, wonderful food.
Your scallops
with wild asparagus.
It's pretty much
our favorite restaurant.
You'll have to come here
for, like, a date night,
those special occasions.
You guys had your wedding
catered by these folks?
We had it here.
You had the wedding here
in PotPie?
Here at PotPie.
We want to feed our people,
and this is our favorite food,
so bring the people here.
WILLIAMS:
Chicken pasta, table four.
Every time I eat here, I think,
"When's the next time we're
gonna get to go back here?"
Ceremony again?
You gonna renew the vows?
When you do it, just make
sure that -- I'll come.
Simple, refined, balanced.
What you see is what you get.
Right.
Well done.
FIERI: Up next...
I can hear
the one squirrel in there
pedaling his heart out.
...we're headed to Nashville...
This is, like,
the healthiest thing
I've ever eaten
on "Triple D."
...for a joint that's rocking
a new trend in town.
If I lived in Nashville,
I'd be by two,
three times a week.
So, I'm about 10 minutes from
downtown Nashville, Tennessee,
right over by the airport.
Now, a lot of people think about
Nashville, what do they think?
They think great music,
killer barbecue.
But you know what?
There's another side.
The eclectic mix of people
that live here.
That's why there's a joint
that's serving up a really
funky, unique, healthy menu.
You got to check out Phat Bites.
Hummus Envy up.
We are so thrilled
that we found Phat Bites.
WOMAN: It's different.
You don't really get
this type of food in Nashville.
Salad Trio in the window.
MAN: I mean, these are
the kind of spots you want,
'cause you just can't eat
barbecue every day.
Exactly.
FIERI: A philosophy that owner
Julie Buhler's been dishing out
since she opened
this funky joint in '02.
You eat good, then
you can eat naughty, too.
That's a hell of a way
to put it, girl.
And it raises
another question...
Why'd you call it "phat"?
Pretty hot and tasty.
And I want it to have fat
sandwiches and skinny salads.
So, for the fat, she's got you
covered with sandwiches
like The Big Jerk with jerk pork
and caramelized onions.
It's awesome.
FIERI: And The Ninja Bomb
with Chinese chicken salad
and -- get this -- granola.
It's like breakfast
in a turkey sandwich.
As for the skinny, how about
at least two dozen
homemade salads every day?
Long Life up!
The Long Life Salad is amazing.
Raw kale salad with beans,
quinoa, kale, nutrients,
you know, something
that's actually gonna give
some life to your body.
The Long Life Salad.
All right.
So, let's get into it.
Black-eyed peas.
Christmas lima beans.
Christmas lima beans?
They're just a little prettier
than regular lima beans.
Yes, they are.
Black beans.
Split lentils.
Here we go.
Coming at you.
All right.
So, these are gonna soak
overnight.
Now, next up?
We're gonna put them
in the pots.
We have to cook them now.
Come up here.
You have to cook them
all individually.
As much as they can handle,
right?
Right there's good.
Okay. So, we got
all of our beans on.
Next up,
we can start red quinoa.
And then just water.
So, that's going. The beans
are going. What's next?
Okay, now we're gonna make
the vinaigrette.
Very nice.
Lemon peel, orange peel.
Bunch of ginger.
I'm gonna process that
just real quick by itself.
What yard sale
did you get that from?
It's just old!
I like it!
I can hear
the one squirrel in there
pedaling his heart out.
Okay, now I have to stop it
just one second.
Coconut oil.
Coconut oil. Yeah.
This thing
is not gonna go another --
It will. It'll be fine.
That was orange juice,
fresh-squeezed?
Fresh-squeezed
orange juice.
Fresh-squeezed lemon juice.
Fresh lemon.
Okay.
And that's our vinaigrette?
Can I taste this?
Yes.
It's very zesty.
Oh, my God. It's --
If you have a cold,
come down
and have just, like,
a taste of the dressing.
There's enough vitamin C in it
for the rest of your life.
It's medicinal.
Medieval is more like it.
Finally, we're almost
to the end of the journey.
I understand why you call it
Long Life Salad.
You have to have a long life
to be able to make it.
Yes.
Hit it.
Ready? Okay.
A whole garden full
of kale.
The beans that we soaked,
then cooked, then rinsed.
And the quinoa.
Christmas lima beans.
Black-eyed peas.
Pecans.
Dried cranberries.
Mangoes.
Plump golden raisins.
Plums. That's a kicker.
You don't see that every day.
Our citrus vinaigrette.
Salt and ground pepper.
Now I'm gonna mix it.
You're gonna get in there,
aren't you?
This is, like,
the healthiest thing
I've ever eaten
on "Triple D."
But serve me up
a handful of this.
Killer. Really good.
This is what I love to eat.
Thank you.
Oh, I'm so glad you liked it.
The crunch of the kale,
the quinoa, the dried mango,
the cranberries --
If you did eat this,
you would have a long life.
Yes.
If I lived in Nashville
or within the surrounding area,
I'd be by two, three times
a week to get this.
Oh!
I wish you lived here.
[ Both laugh ]
Here is your Long Life
Salad plate.
It tastes delicious,
and it's awesome.
I really do feel like 20 years
just got put onto my life.
WOMAN:
The place is special.
It just has a lot of character,
super funky.
Listen, I have been
in some funky joints.
And where are we?
I mean, across the street
from a tire shop,
next to an old car wash
that's all graffiti'ed up.
Which I heard
you had a hand in.
That's mine.
FIERI:
And now it's everybody's,
'cause their customers aren't
just using it for parking.
It's now a giant canvas
for local artists.
We have seen some big
diners, drive-ins, and dives
setups before.
Nothing to this degree.
That's going big "Triple D."
How's that?
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Hey, if anybody has a food
processor at home
they like,
bring it on down.
This thing's
on its last leg.