I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
You might want to stand back.
It gets a little hairy.
...it's all about the PPQ.
Two of my favorite words.
You know --
pork, pasta, and barbecue.
I want to see magic.
Two are
in Kansas City, Missouri...
Give me the rundown.
...one an eclectic
comfort joint...
I carried it in barefoot
by myself.
Uphill both ways.
...singing
a different tune...
[ Humming ]
You're a culinary gangster,
girl.
...the other
a father/son Italian spot...
[ Singing in Italian ]
...that eats like Italy.
So, what do you do
while this is going?
I drink some wine.
And in Albuquerque, New Mexico,
the soul place...
Be easy on me.
I will.
...slow-cooking chicken...
Look at that. Man.
...and deep-frying the dog.
Here's the only thing
I don't like about this,
is I want six of them.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here
in Kansas City, Missouri.
Love this town.
Great food, total characters,
the American Royal --
I mean, come on.
So, my buddy, Stretch,
that owns Grinders --
you remember Stretch?
He was on "Triple D."
It's like seven blocks north
of this place.
He says, "Listen, Guy, I got
a joint you got to check out."
You only got to tell me once.
This is Succotash.
It's the best
place for breakfast in
Kansas City, hands down.
Cake and a smile.
Come in here, and you can hear
them singing.
[ Humming ]
We've got a BLT.
It's eclectic.
FIERI: You can say the same
about Stretch,
the cat who sent me here.
My brother
from another mother says,
"There is a joint
in Kansas City
you got to check out next time
you're in town."
Succotash.
Great food.
Here you are.
Great people.
Peach crepes!
Beth is just a really vivacious,
fun person.
FIERI: That'd be
self-taught chef Beth Barden,
who dove into the restaurant
business back in '01.
What did you do
before this?
I was a sex-ed teacher.
[ Record scratches ]
In '09, she went full DIY
when she moved to Holmes Street.
I put all this up myself.
You tiled
the restaurant yourself?
I tiled it.
I did all the front.
I've always been
very hands-on.
And that definitely applies
to the food.
Plating Farmstand.
WOMAN: Pork hash.
I love the pork hash.
It's just got a great flavor.
All right,
what are we going to make?
We're gonna make pork hash.
Two of my favorite words.
It starts with a rub.
Black pepper,
dark chili powder, paprika,
salt,
a healthy dose of cayenne.
[ Whistles ]
And then this lovely butt
of pork.
But seriously.
Just score
the top of the pork,
and I use a bone-in
so it has
a little more flavor.
Absolutely.
Rub it in, kind of give it
a good -- good spanking.
We'll add a few carrots.
A little mirepoix.
Celery, yellow onion.
Jalapeños?
Jalapeño, mm-hmm.
Whole garlic,
and then water.
And then fresh-pressed
orange juice.
Saran and foil.
[ Whistles ]
For a girl that didn't go
to any culinary school,
you sure know
all the trade secrets.
You really got to lock it in,
keep all that moisture,
steam and cook that pork butt
all at one time.
In the oven, what temp?
275.
15 hours?
Yeah.
Gonna make black beans to go
with the pork hash.
Start
with dried black beans.
[ Southern accent ]
I'm gonna add the water.
The water.
I just pumped it
from the well.
I did. I carried it in barefoot
by myself.
Uphill both ways.
[ Normal voice ] And
then I'm gonna put a
little bit of coffee in there,
and then I'm gonna add
a little bit of yellow onion.
[ Normal voice ] Very nice.
And then a little
granulated garlic.
How long
are these gonna go?
About four hours.
Now we're gonna finish
the beans
with a little chipotle
with adobo.
Fresh lime juice.
White pepper.
And salt.
There you go.
Pork is out of the oven.
It's a little warm,
thank you.
Look at this.
Cooked down.
Mmm.
Oh, that's tasty pork.
The heat from the jalapeño.
Okay.
Then it just goes
into the pan.
It just shreds that easy.
Absolutely.
Okay.
So potatoes are down.
A potato that we bake,
and then we cool them, cut them.
And you take a nice,
generous dose of pork and eggs.
Your favorite.
All right.
Holy hash, Batman.
The tortilla.
All right,
and then the beans.
Delicious verde.
Wow.
Cheese.
And a little homemade pico.
Get freak-o
with the pico.
There you go.
That is the pork hash.
You get some tortilla,
grab a little of that hash,
a little of that salsa,
some of them beans.
Mmm.
It's not
your average breakfast hash,
and that pork is just
really tender, great flavor.
Mmm. The pico's
really nice and fresh.
And the tomatillo sauce is
what makes it for me.
You put a lot of love
into that.
Thank you.
Well done. Killer hash.
WOMAN: The pork hash.
It's crispy and juicy
at the same time.
Just makes you go, "mmm."
That's all I can say about that.
Build your own burrito up.
It's about time that we give you
a little update from the road.
The dynamic duo
of Jane and Roger
happened to meet up with us
here in Kansas City.
How many joints
you guys hit by now?
217.
Without a Food Network budget,
I'm quite impressed.
What do you think of this place?
This is pretty exciting.
Fabulous. Fabulous.
This is great.
This is absolutely great.
The staff is wonderful.
The food is fabulous.
What's happening
in the world, Stretch?
Well, I've been traveling
around the world.
That's great, thank you.
Yeah, it's very good.
It's been awesome
having you.
Stretch,
you're the best.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up, we're staying
in Kansas City...
That's gold.
...but heading to Italy?
This is everything
that you want in lasagna.
Mmm.
So, here I am,
right on the state line,
and I mean on the state line,
between Kansas and Missouri.
Can you imagine,
you walk across the street,
you're in another state?
Well, get ready, 'cause when you
walk through these doors,
you're walking
into another country.
This Italian chef,
he's scratch-making everything.
This is Cupini's.
Lasagna coming out.
It's like a little piece of
Italy coming here. It's crazy.
[ Singing in Italian ]
You can tell it's fresh.
You can tell it's homemade.
FIERI: And for long-time chef
Franco Cupini,
that home is Rome.
How did you end up
in the United States?
Backstroke.
And once Franco
made it across the Atlantic,
he opened this joint
with his son, Eddie, in 2003.
EDDIE: How's
that ravioli, Dad?
Ravioli coming.
What is the specialty
of the house?
FRANCO:
We do all fresh pasta.
For dishes
like seafood ravioli...
You can tell that it was made
with a little bit of love.
...tender gnocchi
and lasagna,
with every layer
made in-house.
Definitely one of my favorite
things on the menu.
What are we making?
We're making the dough
for making the lasagna.
Let's get it going, boss.
Okay.
These machines were imported
from St. Louis?
No, sir. One way,
direct from north Italy.
Semolina first. Okay.
Now regular flour.
Salt, olive oil, eggs.
With a little water.
Now, how long
are we gonna let this go?
10 minutes.
So, what do you do
while this is going?
I drink some wine.
It's in the morning,
though.
I don't care.
It can be 5:00 someplace else
in the world.
Okay, so you wait till that edge
starts to clean up.
There we go, and that's it?
That's it.
Nice and easy. Now we're gonna
take it off and go here?
Then we go here.
And we're making
lasagna sheets, right?
We're making
lasagna sheets.
You want to push
the button?
Okay, green.
Don't get your tie caught
in there, your honor.
Look at this.
A little semolina
so it doesn't stick.
We take it,
and we cut it off.
That's nice.
Now we cut it up?
Yes, sir.
We're all done, brother.
Oh, my goodness,
that's gold.
A little bit of semolina.
We stretch it, and we're
gonna cut them in length.
Got little marks
here on the table.
Si, signore.
Okay.
Now, the water's ready.
We're gonna blanch it.
And then we have an ice bath
we're gonna drop it in,
stop the cooking.
Mm-hmm.
We're gonna start the meat
for making the lasagna.
Got it.
Olive oil.
Celery.
Okay.
Carrots, onion,
bay leaf, chopped garlic,
fresh ground beef.
Salt?
A little bit of salt.
How long is this gonna cook?
This gonna cook
about 15 minutes.
Then can we make
the lasagna?
Si, signore.
Okay, boss.
We start with marinara sauce
at the bottom.
Evenly. Then we start
with the layers of pasta.
Marinara. Béchamel.
Okay.
Push around a little bit.
Adding ground beef.
Fresh mozzarella.
Romano.
How many layers of this?
About six.
We cover it up.
We put them in the oven
for about 35 minutes.
And then take it off, foil off,
and we let it crust the top.
Bring it.
Lasagna, pronta.
I'm gonna eat all of this.
All righty, here we are.
Nice little fresh marinara sauce
in the center.
This is everything
that you want in lasagna.
Delicate, really good pasta.
It is ridiculous.
Like, when I think of lasagna
in the morning for breakfast --
'cause that's
what I think about --
that's the lasagna.
Seriously,
this is vicious and delicious.
Mmm.
Fantastic lasagna dish.
FIERI: No surprise, since Franco
spent 45 years
cooking for everybody
from the president of Italy
to high-end hotel chains,
and he loved to rock out
the rustic on this menu...
Dino pizza coming up.
Got the tortellini.
...scratch-made
from top to bottom,
using his papa's recipe
for chicken and prosciutto.
Ground roasted chicken,
prosciutto, what else?
We assemble it
in a mixer.
One egg, pepper, salt,
Romano, bread crumbs,
a little parsley,
and finally, ricotta.
And now...
[ Mixer squeals ]
That thing's
on its last leg, huh?
No, this has a lot of miles.
We're ready to go.
All right, Chef.
I want to see magic.
A little semolina
on the table.
Now we beat our eggs.
[ Whistles ]
We fold them in half.
Okay.
We open it back again,
and then we take a little pan
over here, a rolling pan.
A rolling pan?
That's called a pizza cutter.
Wet it.
Thank you, sir.
Doctor? Doctor?
Very nice.
Doctor?
We're gonna ball it up
in our hands,
a little bit at a time.
And then cover it up,
cut it.
Okay.
Then what we're doing --
you just fold a little bit,
and push it back
and pinch it,
and you got tortellini.
Guess who's making that
at home.
Now?
What we do is starting
a little sauce.
Put the olive oil, chopped
onions, and a little cream.
Okay. We can put the tortellini
on the same time.
The salted water, okay.
Takes three minutes.
Black pepper, okay.
A little bit of Béchamel.
We put the marinara.
[ Speaks Italian ]
Swirl to have
a little pinkish color, nice.
Roasted pepper,
and now a pinch of salt.
Ting, ting, that's it.
Here we are.
Pinch of the grated Romano,
and we are ready to go.
And then we're ready
to do this.
Si.
And enough cheese to sink
the Titanic.
That's ridiculous.
Tons of flavor,
handmade tortellini.
You can see
all the ground chicken
and the prosciutto
and the cream sauce.
Not really heavy.
Everything's from scratch.
What a deal.
It's creamy,
and it's really, really good.
Nothing can beat Cupini's.
The best Italian food
I've ever had.
The food is outrageous,
and you --
you just got to cut
all the walls down,
put the stage right there.
[ Laughter,
indistinct conversations ]
FIERI: Up next...
I got to get
a picture of that.
...we're headed to Albuquerque,
New Mexico...
Fry the dog.
...for a taste
of some legit southern soul.
You nail it, you nail it,
you nail it.
So, here I am
in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
I love coming down here.
I mean, great weather, tons
of culture, and you know what?
We always find
really cool "Triple D" joints.
So, I'm here on Central Avenue.
Now, this was
the original Route 66,
and it doesn't get more "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives" than that.
We're here to check out a joint
that's smoking it, pickling it,
baking it, all from scratch.
This is The Cube.
Brisket with mac and cheese,
collards, and cornbread.
We just love the food.
Even the folks seem to have a
different view of what that is.
Upscale Memphis barbecue.
Pulled pork sandwich,
mac and cheese side, order up.
This is soul food.
Sometimes we call it
Manny's joint.
FIERI: That makes sense,
'cause Queens native Manny Aka
has been driving this train
since it opened in '09...
They make everything
except the plates.
...with a little help
from his grandpa's
rock-solid southern recipes.
WOMAN: I got your chicken
with yams and collard greens.
I ordered the smoked
barbecue chicken.
...which is just so good.
So, we're gonna work
on some smoked chicken.
AKA: First, you have
your butterflied chicken,
and you're gonna make
your buttermilk marinade.
I'm gonna?
I'm gonna make it, okay?
There you go.
First you start
with your buttermilk, onions.
Then you got your pepper,
salt, sugar, garlic.
All right, these bad boys are
going for at least four hours,
but overnight is definitely
the best way to go.
Now, the dry rub?
Yes.
Start off with paprika,
pepper, celery salt,
granulated garlic,
kosher salt,
cumin, mustard powder,
brown sugar,
ancho chili powder, parsley,
and some sugar.
Just whisk it all
till it's uniform,
just so it can be
as even as possible.
Now you have
your marinated chicken.
Right here is
your seasoned salt --
just pepper, salt, garlic.
That's it. And this goes on
before your rub.
Now we go with this rub.
Sprinkle it on.
You don't want it on too thick.
You don't want to bite into,
like, a whole bunch of rub.
Is this gonna stay marinated
again after it gets all this?
Yeah, definitely,
at least four hours,
but again,
it's better overnight.
And then we finally go
to the smoker?
3 to 5 hours at 225.
What kind of pellets?
A mix of hickory and cherry.
Now it's ready to roll.
Here we go.
[ Whistles ]
Whoa.
Coming at you,
right behind you.
Look at that. Man!
Now that these guys are out,
we let them rest.
That's good-looking smoke.
I got to get a picture of that.
All charred and everything
like that.
That's gorgeous.
Aw, really nice.
Juicy.
That brine with the buttermilk,
how that comes together.
So, the smoke's
not overpowering.
Different smoke will give you
different colors.
People look at it and go, "Wait
a minute, that's not cooked."
This bird is totally,
totally cooked.
It's the smoke that gives
that little pink tinge.
Mmm. Mmm!
So, there's
our smoked chicken.
Now we're gonna baste it with
our homemade barbecue sauce.
You're gonna get a little crust,
a little bit of char.
Another level of flavor.
Constantly flip it
so it doesn't get overcooked.
One more coat.
Right to the plate.
Wow.
Now we're ready
for the collard greens.
Dig it.
Get a nice bowlful.
You really want to get
a lot of that broth,
'cause that's what took
all the time.
And that's all she wrote.
Texas toast is made in-house
every single day.
Oh! It's great smoke,
really tangy barbecue sauce.
Mmm. Wow.
The broth is great.
Not too salty. A little bite
of the vinegar.
A healthy amount of that
shredded hock and turkey leg.
You got to dig in.
Get that ladled up
right like that.
Huh? Right like that.
You nail it, man.
You nail it, you nail it,
you nail it.
It is divine.
WOMAN: You can taste
the smoked flavor
all the way
through the chicken.
Absolutely delicious.
I have a New Mexican burger,
order up.
WOMAN: I thought, why am I
ordering a burger at a barbecue?
And the burger floored me.
FIERI: And from what I hear,
same goes for the dogs.
Tell me
about this hot dog.
AKA: We're making
a Guadalajara dog.
Guadalajara dog?
Yes.
All right,
when you come back,
we'll make
the Guadalajara dog.
We're hanging out at The Cube
in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
Be easy on me.
I will.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out in
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
Now, it's called The Cube.
Dude is scratch-making it all.
I'm talking about
from the brines to the sauces.
I mean, he's smoking it,
he's cooking it.
And now, we're on
to the Guadalajara dog.
I have
a Guadalajara dog.
It's fantastic, 'cause it has
chipotle mayonnaise.
Give me the rundown.
All right.
You're gonna take
your all-beef frank,
take this thick slice
of applewood-smoked bacon.
Hang on a second.
Equal weight, practically.
Look at the side of that.
Half a pig.
Only way to go.
Okay.
Couple toothpicks,
keep it together.
What sauce are we making?
We're making
a chipotle sauce.
We have your chipotle peppers
in adobo that have been pureed.
You dump it
in the sour cream.
Beautiful.
You blend it until it is
all the same color.
Dig it. Fry the dog.
All right.
So, it'll crisp up the dog,
cook the bacon.
And we'll be done.
All right.
We want to put on
a good amount
of the chipotle sauce.
After that, you top it off
with your pico.
Nice, healthy serving
of it. Now we're ready.
There's something about
that naturally cased hot dog.
You get that snap,
like a real casing on it.
Crunchy bacon
on the outside,
spicy sour cream
from the chipotle,
and then the freshness
of the pico de gallo.
Mmm.
That is gangster.
Here's the only thing
I don't like about this,
is I want six of them.
Here's your Guadalajara dog.
WOMAN: The hot dog
is cooked perfectly.
Like, you bite in,
and the skin bursts,
and all the juice gets you.
They're just awesome here.
This is exactly
the kind of place
we want to find
on "Triple D."
Dude, you're knocking it
out of the park.
Thank you.
Manny, you the man.
Barbe-cube.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I got to tell you,
what a blast.
Thanks for recommending.
This is real --
Did Gorilla just walk by?
Weird.
You didn't even have
a line, Gorilla.