Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
How's that feel?
...we're headed to Tennessee...
Now you're cooking
with gas.
...for some honky-tonk
holiday traditions.
BOTH:
That's important.
In the city
of Hendersonville...
Well, I cleaned up for you.
This is Sunday best.
...pulled pork done
to perfection
and a sweet take on ham...
I don't even really know
what to say at this point.
...just built
for the centerpiece.
Was that a growl
you just made?
And in East Nashville...
Just wait.
I can't wait anymore.
...the funky Mexican joint
scratch-making
a festive masa masterpiece.
The holiday tamale.
Holiday tamales.
And one traditional
seasonal soup.
Every once in a while,
I get one of those OMG moments.
That just hit a new level.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
I'm in the great state
of Tennessee --
one of my favorites.
Why?
Well, home of Jack Daniels,
the Grand Ole Opry,
and some killer barbecue.
Now, I'm in Hendersonville,
about 10 miles from Nashville,
on the corner of Center Point
and Main Street
to check out a joint
that's got a ton of character
and a bunch of stories.
This is Center Point Barbecue.
Brisket. Corn on the cob.
Spicy red slaw.
The best barbecue in the south.
Pulled pork.
This is authentic
as you're gonna get.
Everybody loves their barbecue.
FIERI: 'Cause when it comes
to smoking meat,
owner Robert Duke
doesn't mess around.
You're the cleanest
pit master I know.
Well, I cleaned up for you.
This is my Sunday best.
And the smell coming
from his three smoke pits
is like a come-and-get-it bell
for the locals.
Generally, I think you can
smell it about a mile away.
Just makes your taste buds
want to drop by and eat it.
FIERI: Whether it's a full rack
of ribs, smoky beef brisket,
or one of Robert's down-home
family traditions.
Pulled pork.
There's no other pulled pork
around that even compares to it.
This is the entire
shoulder together.
Not gonna mess around.
Bone in.
We're gonna make
our marinades.
A gallon of mild sauce.
Two gallons of vinegar.
Now what are we gonna do?
We're gonna mop it, and,
just like I said, generously.
Let's do a little rub.
Do a little crazy pepper here.
Crazy pepper?
Let's love on it
just a little bit.
A little bit of salt.
Not much.
And that's it? Getting it
ready for the smoker.
What are we gonna
smoke it with?
Shagbark hickory.
Shagbark hickory?
We get a lot of smoke
out of that.
BOTH:
That's important.
[ Laughing ]
Get me overalls.
I'm staying.
Ready to go.
Let's go.
Look at this monster.
225.
225. That's it.
For 18 hours?
Anything more
than that's a sin.
We're gonna cook
fat side up,
and it's just gonna keep on
basting itself as it turns.
I got you. Hit it.
That's black as night.
We're smoking.
What is the yield you're getting
off of this thing?
At 50, 55.
55%?
Right.
That's redonkulus.
[ Whistles ]
Look at the bark on that, Man.
That is crazy.
You want to bust
this thing open?
It ain't gonna take much.
So, what we're gonna do --
we're just gonna bust it
down the middle.
Pull it back.
Just let it go. All right?
We're gonna let you get
your own meat out of there,
so if you want over here
or you over here
or you want up here,
it's your choice.
Well, I'm gonna take
a little bit up here.
That's the good part.
I love that part right there.
Yeah. I like that up there
where there's more movement.
You know? Up in that --
There you go.
Dig right up in there.
See that right in there?
Peek-a-boo, I see you.
Oh, yeah. That's it.
Oh, yeah. There you go.
That's what
we're talking about.
So, it comes with a whole
heaping of pickles,
and what's that --
A pancake?
It's our cornbread patty.
So, I don't like putting
my sauce on my meat.
I like to have it there
to dip.
Mmm.
I'm telling you.
I got to tell you
something.
The pork has been cooked down
to a point
that you don't see
very often.
A little heat, a little sweet
right on your meat.
Awesome job.
That's what I think barbecue
should taste like.
The pulled pork is some of
the best I've had anywhere.
It just melts in your mouth.
It is really good.
This little restaurant's been
here since I was a little kid.
Some of my first memories here
with my dad
getting a barbecue sandwich.
I remember coming in here
as a little girl,
and it would be
wall-to-wall people.
FIERI:
Full of friends, neighbors,
and...the occasional
country music star.
Everybody that's on the wall
has been here,
and we've serviced them.
From the Man in Black
to Taylor Swift.
And then there's one of
my personal favorites.
Sleepy LaBeef
and the Macaronis.
You don't remember them?
Oh, yes.
Rocking.
Got that on eight-track.
And if I had to guess,
I bet when he was here,
old Sleepy snacked
on this Southern staple...
Fried green tomatoes.
...topped with Robert's
own yum yum sauce.
You eat them here,
you'll come back
and order them
time and time again.
This is yum yum sauce
we're making?
Yum yum sauce.
We're doing about half a gallon
Thousand Island.
Chili powder.
Cayenne.
Horseradish.
Thousand Island
with a big kick.
I'm telling you.
Next up?
Flour power.
Okay. Hit it.
All-purpose flour?
All-purpose.
Cornmeal.
Crazy salt.
Black pepper.
Center Point's
own garlic herb blend.
Garlic herb blend?
Blend.
So, this is the typical dredge
that's gonna go together.
Big slab of green tomato.
Little wet.
Little egg wash.
And now to the fryer.
These are hot.
Okay.
Yum yum.
Sour cream.
Little bit.
We're gonna add a little touch
of color to it.
There she is.
Why are you so reserving
on the yum yum sauce?
Oh, I can give you
some more if you like.
You can always put on,
but you can't take off.
Mmm.
I like fried green tomatoes
because of the tang.
And then the yum yum sauce on it
has got a little spice.
When they cool down
a little bit
and they're not burning
your tongue off,
that's when they're key.
Great cornmeal crunch
to it.
Nice fresh green tomato.
Delicious.
Good, huh?
[ Both chuckle ]
He understands.
He speaks
Barbecue-nese.
Fried green tomatoes up,
please.
The fried green tomatoes just
take you back to the South.
No regular tomatoes.
He'll only eat
fried green tomatoes.
Really?!
WOMAN: They just have a flavor
of their own here.
When you taste them,
you always come back for me.
So, here's the deal --
great barbecue,
tons of history,
but I got to tell you something.
There's one thing I have heard
about Center Point Barbecue,
and it is this sugar-glazed,
honey-smoked ham.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
hanging out
in Hendersonville, Tennessee.
This guy is gonna blow it up
with a killer ham.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
hanging out for the holidays at
the Center Point Barbecue joint
here in Hendersonville,
Tennessee.
We are getting ready
to do a holiday ham
like we've never
seen before.
Is it time?
We're ready to dip.
Bring on the brine.
Let's do it.
We'll start off
with two gallons of water here.
Salt.
Sugar.
Equal parts salt and sugar.
Got you.
Cloves. Cinnamon.
Cinnamon-amon-amon.
Little pickling spice?
Just a little bit.
And then
white clove honey.
White clove honey.
How do you know?
Says it on the bottle.
Okay.
We're gonna bring this
to a boil.
Then let it cool down.
So, our ham trimmed up,
going in the brine.
How long are we gonna
let it brine?
We're gonna go four days.
Four days
it's gonna brine? Nice.
Does it go to the smoker?
Ready to go.
It's about six hours.
225. That's it.
It's pretty ham.
Next up?
Making the glaze.
Brown sugar.
Cloves.
Black pepper.
Sugar. Cinnamon.
Mix that together.
Get the moisture out of it,
put it in the shaker,
And we're ready to
glaze the ham then.
Okay.
Ready, Guy?
Hang on a second.
Let's warm this thing up
a little bit.
Now you're cooking
with gas!
Sugar
in the ham seasoning.
This is the ham seasoning.
I have far too much
hair-care product
to be messing around
with a torch like that.
[ Laughter ]
We got to let that rest.
Oh, you think?!
Yeah.
I don't even really know
what to say at this point.
I have seen some things
in my day.
That one, I'm gonna
need some therapy for.
Wow. It's hard
like an Easter egg.
Let's get into this.
[ Grunts ]
Was that a growl
you just made?
Mmm.
You haven't even had
any yet,
and you're grunting
and growling.
[ Grunts ]
That's all this love
down in here -- ah!
You guys got to see this.
Look at the bark.
Beautiful.
[ Grunts ]
Well, it's delicious.
I got to tell you something.
At certain parts of that,
almost like brittle.
Like ham brittle.
I'll tell you something -- every
once in awhile on "Triple D,"
you got to bring in authority
who really knows
what food tastes like.
Get over here, Ethan.
Watch yourself.
Got your gloves on?
Get over here, Coop.
Let's see what these two
little lunch faces think.
What do you think?
It's really good.
Is it really good?
Dude, give me a...
[ Mumbles ]
The good stuff!
There you go.
Hey!
Ham plate up, please.
The smoked ham is fantastic.
So wonderful
during the holidays.
It just is a delight
to my family table.
Outstanding, my friend.
FIERI: Coming up...
Another holiday dish.
Another.
We're staying festive
with a trip to East Nashville...
I'm not kidding you.
Look at that grin right there.
"Uh-huh. I know."
...for this tasty
Mexican tradition.
This is got to be one of
the best we've ever had.
So, I'm here
in East Nashville, Tennessee.
Now, I think I'm like you guys.
I'm going to a town --
I start calling family
and friends and saying,
"Hey. Where should I go?
Where is my next
'Triple D' joint?"
Well, you know
I love Martin's Bar-B-Que,
so I called up my boy, Pat.
I said, "Pat, I need a joint.
Where should I..."
He says, "Listen.
Do not leave town
without checking out
this joint."
This is Mas Tacos Por Favor.
Got tacos for Andrea.
The food is wonderful.
FIERI: That's what this guy
keeps telling me.
Pat Martin
of Martin's Bar-B-Que.
Why do you think
this place rocks?
They make everything
from scratch.
Fresh food, local food,
and I wonder how do they do it.
FIERI:
By going right to the source,
which is exactly where
self-trained chef
Teresa Mason headed.
She did her homework.
She went down
and lived in Mexico
and came back up here
and knocked it out.
In a 1974 Winnebago
turned mobile kitchen.
She was a very, very popular
stop after a late night out.
In 2010, she found an old deli
and continued to crank out
authentic Mexican.
Hey, Ben, I got
one tamale going out.
One of the best places in town
for tamales.
Hot tamale.
FIERI: But you can only get them
on Wednesdays or the holidays.
It's amazing.
FIERI:
A Christmas tradition
of masa and spicy filling
steamed in husks
and topped
with a green tomatillo salsa.
We're gonna make these special
for Christmastime.
The Holiday Tamale?
The Holiday Tamales.
Now we're gonna make
the masa.
It's just cornmeal that's been
ground special for tamales.
We'll put
a little baking powder
because I like them
to fluff up a little bit.
To puff up a bit.
Yep.
Put a little salt.
And I just mix that up.
So, we've got our broth.
We make this.
It's a homemade
chicken broth.
We put a little lime
and a lot of peppers in this.
I like to stir a little bit.
Here, I'll stir that.
What's next?
Okay, we need lard.
Is that chicken fat?
It's chicken fat.
The thing I like to do --
I whip it up
so it'll be nice and airy.
Get out!
Get out.
It works, too.
These are really good.
I'm impressed.
These are really nice.
So, now you can just start
scooping that right into here.
These are gonna be fluffy.
Fluffy.
And we're done.
We made masa.
Every once in while
I get one of those OMG moments.
That right there --
that just hit a new level.
Next, we're gonna make
the tinga for the tamales.
The who?
The tinga for the tamales.
What is the tinga?
It's the filling that's gonna
go in the middle.
That's what you call it?
Tinga?
Yeah. That's what
I really call it.
So, tomatoes,
if you leave them alone
and let them burst,
and, so -- yes.
That's what
you're listening for.
we're looking for?
Yeah.
Just want to add
some onions and some garlic.
Get it roasted down.
All right.
So, we got that all cooked down.
And then we're gonna
transfer it into a blender.
We've got
some chipotle peppers.
Yep. With adobo.
Salt.
That's it. Blend it.
Just a little bit
'cause I like it to be
a little bit chunky.
You want some chunk.
Give it a little taste.
[ Sighs ]
That's a tinga.
Yeah.
Now, let's roll them.
Okay, then.
This is just baked
pulled chicken.
Put this on there and mix it
around a little bit.
Okay.
If you'll wring
those out for me.
Wring them?
Those are corn husks.
We soak them
in the warm water
just so they'll be
a little bit more pliable.
You take some masa.
And then
just one little mush.
Got it.
We've got the tinga here.
Put it in the middle
and roll it up.
I try not to be too wild
at making it perfect
because the steam
will fix that.
And then I like this little tuck
you do like that.
Tie it with a bow.
And then that's it.
How long are you
gonna steam these?
For about 20 minutes.
Tamales are ready.
Pull it out.
Hot tamale is great
when it's served
right out of the pot.
It's gonna be the best.
It's still steaming.
Now, do you do this
to everybody?
You open it all up?
Yeah. Yeah.
This is how you get it.
I put a little
tomatillo sauce on top.
And that's it.
It's ready to go.
[ Exhales ]
I'm not kidding you.
Look at that grin right there.
"Uh-huh. I know."
The tomatillo salsa --
spot on.
Coming together with the masa --
the super-light masa
with the whipped chicken fat.
I mean, that is fluffy,
tender...spicy.
This has got to be one of
the best I've ever had.
Okay.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
Wow.
These are great tamales.
Good, soft, tender.
The tomatillo sauce
is absolutely delicious.
Do you like eating here?
Yeah.
What do you like
about it?
Tacos, lemonade.
It's all about the food.
It's simple, fresh ingredients.
We will come here just for
Teresa's lovely soups.
Pazolé for Aaron.
Chicken pazolé soup.
It is phenomenal.
We're gonna make
pazolé verde.
Another holiday dish.
Another.
Gonna start
by making corn stock.
I put the whole cob
in there.
Onions and whole garlic.
Then some water.
Cover it.
Let this boil, and it's gonna
simmer for a couple hours.
And then we'll strain it.
We'll have
a really delicious stock.
And this is our corn stock.
Corn stock.
We're gonna mix the corn stock
with chicken stock.
My chicken stock has
the lime, habanero, jalapeño.
So, we've roasted poblano
peppers on that flat grill.
Then I just skin these,
and I like to cut the top off,
but other than that,
I leave them alone.
Tomatillos, garlic,
and jalapeños.
Yep.
Cilantro.
Just everything green.
Stems and all?
Yeah, it tastes the same.
A little salt.
A few red onions.
Just pour right down
into our broth.
Just wait.
I can't wait anymore.
Back on stove
for a few hours.
First we add the chicken.
Just added the hominy,
the cabbage, the avocado,
a little bit of radish,
some cilantro, some limes.
Just taste
a little of that broth.
[ Grunts ]
The depth of the broth
is ridiculous.
The spiciness is not spicy hot,
it's spicy rich.
The cabbage
is cut perfectly.
The chicken is just tender,
fall apart, shreddinesh-ness.
The hominy's tender.
Avocado starts to melt
into it
and becomes nice and creamy.
A little brightness
from the cilantro.
Out of bounds.
Off the hook.
Happy Holidays.
Pazolé verde.
MARTIN:
An absolute masterpiece.
It's got a really nice little
spicy kick to it.
The broth is really tasty.
FIERI: These are friends of mine
from Sonoma County.
What do you think of this?
Amazing.
It's great Mexican food
outside of California.
This is the place to go.
It really is.
Really is.
We can't leave
Mas Tacos Por Favor.
No, we cannot leave.
Got to make a taco?
We're gonna take
a small break.
When we come back,
we're gonna make a taco
in honor
of my little sister.
We got two quinoa up.
The quinoa and...
Sweet potato.
Taco?
Taco.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
Nashville, Tennessee.
"Triple D" hanging out
at a killer joint
called Mas Tacos Por Favor.
We have had the bomb
holiday tamale.
Then we had pazolé.
Not just any pazolé,
but pazolé magnifico.
So, in honor
of my sister Morgan,
who was a big-time
vegetarian,
we are going to have
a quinoa and...
Sweet potato.
...sweet potato taco.
Okay.
Some habaneros.
Yep.
Got to have a little heat.
How's that feel?
We're gonna put these
in the oven
and just really low-roast them
because we're gonna make
a spice out of these.
These are habaneros.
Get out.
They're a shell
of a habanero.
So, I just blend them up
real quick.
So, we're gonna make
the quinoa.
Sweet potatoes --
cubed, peeled, and diced.
Put that
right on top of there.
Jalapeños.
We like it a little spicy.
And, 'cause
we really like it spicy,
we'll put those peppers
in there.
The dust.
Folks around here
call it the "shake."
They're addicted to it. We set
it out for your tacos, too.
You put that in a shaker jar
for people?
Yeah.
Water.
Beverage sales go up.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
I'm gonna let it
come to a boil
and let it simmer
for 20 minutes.
So, we're gonna
make a taco.
You need a tortilla.
That's the only thing
we don't do in-house.
That's a good-looking
tortilla.
It's incredible.
This one's for your sis.
Quinoa sweet potato.
We'll put it in.
Fill it up.
Fresh shaved cabbage.
That same tomatillo salsa
that you like
with a little crema
right on top.
And then, of course,
cilantro and lime.
Wow.
That's delicious. Creative.
It's hearty.
The sweetness of the sweet
potato, texture of the quinoa,
crunch of the cabbage.
You get a little bit
of that habanero,
you get a little bit of that
acid from the tomatillo.
I had to give up a lot of
options on the menu to try this
'cause I can't eat everything,
and it was so worth it.
Bringing
the family down?
Something different
and something special.
Bursting with flavor.
I'm eating the rest
of this damn thing.
I can tell you that right now.
It's too damn good.
[ Laughter ]
Off the hook.
This girl's dangerous.
Watch yourself
when you're in Nashville.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."