Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Holla!
Challah.
...I'm getting a bite...
I'm stacking it up
for maximum shove-age.
...of some authentic
neighborhood knockouts.
Making it rain
up in here.
In San Diego's
Hillcrest area...
So, you have
Grandma's seal of approval?
Yes.
...the down-home diner...
I mean, that's, like,
half dessert, half breakfast.
...serving up
round-the-clock comfort.
This is a level of juice
you probably haven't seen
on a burger.
In the Tenderloin district
of San Francisco...
That's like
a Pink Floyd concert, man.
...a gourmet-hot-dog spot...
All for the love
of mustard and sausages.
...with a floor show,
to boot.
Wow.
And in Portland, Oregon's
industrial area...
Fire it up.
...the father-and-son joint
making both the meals
and the place
straight from scratch.
You're taking hash
to another hash-alistic level.
Trying.
You should be proud
of that one.
Thank you.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Sea gulls squawking ]
Man, you have got to love
San Diego.
Look at this town --
Great weather, cool people,
and unique restaurants.
So, I'm here
in the Hillcrest neighborhood
to check out a joint that has
healthy, hearty comfort food.
This is the Crest Café.
MAN: This neighborhood is
sort of a 24-hour neighborhood,
and that's the same here
at the Crest.
He's your
crème brûlée French toast.
You can have any dish
on the menu
at any time of day.
Butter burger with fries
and a pulled pork
with cottage cheese.
[ Bell dings ]
Up. Let's go.
"Wow, what do I want?
I mean, that looks good.
That looks good."
And it's just like
you're amongst family.
FIERI: 'Cause you are.
This joint's been run
by the same family since '85,
and today, owners Cecelia Moreno
and Chef Ruben Medina are
leading the charge.
You guys are cousins?
We are.
Ruben actually grew up
with my grandparents
in San Diego.
FIERI: And Grandma's the one
responsible
for teaching Ruben how to cook.
FIERI: So, she came in
and saw the recipes
that she taught you
how to make, and...
She okayed them.
She okayed them?
Yes.
So, you have
Grandma's seal of approval?
Yes.
Even for recipes
he came up with all by himself,
like the chicken-apple hash,
pumpkin-gingerbread pancakes,
or this straight-up,
out-of-bounds sweet treat.
I've got
a crème brûlée French toast up.
It's totally just like getting
dessert for breakfast.
It's absolutely fantastic.
Let's get
into making this.
Heavy cream.
I'm over here just checking
the bacon, buddy.
Ricotta cheese.
Honey.
Darling.
Sweetheart.
Vanilla, orange zest.
And this is all gonna go
for the crème brûlée
French toast?
Got it.
What are we making?
Crème brûlée sauce.
So, we melt butter,
brown sugar.
Then you add
the maple syrup.
So, you mix all this
till the sauce thickens.
Then you add
the vanilla.
Make a nice little caramel?
Yep.
And reduce
by about what --
A third.
All right, so, this is done.
The whipped cream's done.
Now we make
the French toast.
Okay.
What are we gonna use?
What type of bread?
Challah bread?
Challah bread.
Holla!
Challah.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
The dredge for
the crème brûlée French toast.
Okay.
Scrambled eggs.
Heavy cream.
Cinnamon and sugar.
Vanilla extract.
Mix it all up.
Slice the bread.
We're gonna add
a little bit of oil.
And then we're gonna
let it cook.
So, it gets a little crust
on both sides.
Okay, so, we cut it up
diagonally.
Then we're gonna hit it
with the, uh...
Whipped cream.
Fresh strawberries.
And then
the crème brûlée sauce.
That's it, huh?
Pretty good.
I mean, that's half dessert,
half breakfast.
It's excellent.
Right amount of French toast.
Right thickness of it.
It's not soggy.
Not too sweet.
The whipped cream
with the ricotta in it...
gives it a richness
and a little bit of tang
with the zest
of the orange.
It's a great balance.
Good job, buddy.
Thanks, Guy.
Appreciate it.
I'm impressed.
Crème brûlée
French toast up.
Have you tried
the crème brûlée French toast?
Absolutely.
Ridiculous.
I can't get enough of it.
We never rest
on our laurels.
I always like to try
new things,
and then I have to see
if he would like
to execute it.
FIERI: The results?
You got it --
more outrageousness,
like this monster.
I have
your butter burger.
It's the juiciest hamburger
you can ever imagine.
All right,
what are we making?
We're making the butter
for the butter burger.
So, literally,
there's butter in a burger?
Yes. One block.
Fresh basil,
fresh parsley.
Fresh tarragon,
fresh garlic.
Cayenne.
A little salt
and pepper.
Then we're gonna
whisk it all up.
So, the butter's got to be
room temperature.
Otherwise,
you got yourself a big mess.
That's right.
So, we'll let this set up?
I'm gonna grab
some plastic wrap.
Put the butter
on the plastic wrap,
and you just roll it.
And then you put it
in the refrigerator so it sets.
Right, so it hardens up.
Now we're going to stuff butter
in a burger.
This is our herb butter.
Yes.
Take off
some of the meat.
Put the butter
in the burger.
Yeah, the butter.
And hide it.
And you're gonna cook this
on the flattop?
No, on the broiler.
Really?
Yeah.
This is gonna be
interesting.
A little more butter?
Yep,
a little bit more butter.
And then the cheese.
Once the cheese melts,
then we'll put it on the bun
like that.
Then we're gonna add
the garlic mayo to the cheese.
Whoa!
Watch this,
ladies and gentlemen.
This is a level of juice
you probably haven't seen
on a burger.
Making it rain
up in here.
[ Chuckles ]
Where's
the umbrellas at?
[ Chuckles ]
Wow.
That is juicy.
It has tons of flavor.
That's ridiculous,
what you're doing.
When it says, "butter burger,"
take the dude's word for it.
Nice job.
Thanks.
Excellent burger.
Thanks, Guy.
Ends up being the juiciest thing
you'd ever had.
Got a butter burger.
Did they give you, like,
a poncho or a parka
that you could just...?
[ Laughs ]
You're scratch-making
your food.
You take a tremendous amount
of pride.
The only thing that you're gonna
have a concern with is
you're gonna need a [Whispering]
little bit larger place --
a little bit
bigger.
You think?
Yeah.
I don't know.
Small's kind of sweet.
Oh, yeah?
FIERI: Coming up...
Let's get
into this sandwich.
...we're headed
to San Francisco,
California...
Real-deal dogs.
for the old hot dog...
Whoa!
and chicken show.
It should say
"Show Chicken."
So, I'm here in the Tenderloin
district of San Francisco,
right on the corner
of Market and Golden Gate,
to check out a hot dog-joint --
Not just any hot dog joint.
I mean,
this is San Francisco.
They love food in this town.
This place, they're
scratch-making the mustard,
the ketchup,
and the gourmet dogs.
This is Show Dogs.
Wild-boar sausage.
I love hot dogs, so finding
a place like this was awesome.
And the all-beef dog.
This is definitely
not your average hot dog.
Every dish has
a different twist to it.
FIERI:
'Cause owner John Clark isn't
just a businessman.
He's a flat-out food dude.
My background as a chef is
to make everything in-house.
It's the opposite
of fast food.
So, he brought in
Chef Seth Carter...
Polish dog. Order up.
...and together,
they've created a menu
full of scratch-made sodas,
sauces, and sides
to pair with their
gourmet dogs and sandwiches,
like this high-end clucker.
Fried-chicken sandwich.
Order up.
It is so tasty.
It's so good.
We are making
the spice mixture
that we use to marinate
the chicken
for the fried-chicken
sandwich.
So, we have kosher salt.
Vinegar power.
Vinegar powder?
Vinegar powder.
Onion powder.
Madras curry powder.
Turmeric.
Garlic powder.
Black pepper.
Toasted ground cumin.
Bring it together?
Bring it together.
We have grape-seed oil.
We're gonna put some of that
over the chicken...
Look at that beautiful color
on that grape-seed oil.
...and spoon some
of the marinade over it.
And then we're gonna
mix it up.
How long are we gonna
let this marinate?
A couple hours.
We got
our marinated chicken.
We're gonna add the salt
to the flour.
A.P. flour?
A.P. flour.
Okay.
All right.
Chicken --
We put in the flour.
Get it in the buttermilk.
Flour sticks
to the chicken.
Buttermilk sticks
to the flour.
And back into the flour.
And that's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
We're gonna fry this
for about two minutes,
and then we'll be
ready to go.
We take the bottom bun,
slather it with our
lemon-cayenne aioli
that we make
here in-house.
Slather?
Slather.
It's a very specific word.
Our house-made coleslaw.
Our pickled ginger
that we also make in-house.
[ Whistles ]
There's
our fried chicken.
And slather this bun
with our lemon-cayenne aioli
again.
And there we go.
Let's get
into this sandwich.
Whew!
Shut the front door!
That fried chicken is
out-of-bounds.
Yeah.
This is -- Whoa.
There's flavor
all over the board on this one.
That's like
a Pink Floyd concert, man.
[ Laughs ]
Classic.
It is a classic,
but wow.
Yes.
The crunch from the chicken
and the saltiness to it is
just perfectly
in balance.
That is an awesome
fried-chicken sandwich.
Mmm!
Thank you.
It should say
"Show Chicken."
[ Laughs ]
Here's
the fried-chicken sandwich.
Out of the chicken sandwiches
I've had,
this is, by far,
my favorite.
Pretty redunkulous.
Yeah.
This chicken
I almost ate off his plate
'cause it's so good.
FIERI: And while the food is
definitely the star here,
it's not the only show
in town...
MAN: The entertainment.
It's just going down
all the time?
Oh, yeah.
It's a great part of town.
...'cause the windows
in this triangle-shaped joint
give a 180-degree glimpse
of some of San Francisco's
finest...
Yo!
This is a very, um,
flavorful neighborhood.
Lively.
...which makes it
the perfect backdrop
for their funky dogs,
like this
North-African sausage...
MAN:
Here's your lamb merguez.
...topped
with a custom-made mustard.
It's delicious.
All right, Chef.
So, what are we making?
We're gonna make our house-made
Dijon-style mustard
that we're gonna use
on our lamb-merguez sausage.
Got it.
The first thing
we're gonna do is
we're going to take
our raw, organic,
yellow mustard seeds.
They're going to soak
for about two days.
We're gonna pour them
into our little dish here.
We've got
champagne vinegar.
our Chardonnay.
Chardonnay?
Chardonnay.
Raw, organic sugar.
Organic garlic powder.
And, of course,
our kosher salt.
Mustard needs
lots of salt.
Stir this up.
Here we go.
[ Blender whirring ]
We will let it cure
for a day or so.
Then we'll blend it again.
Mmm.
Exactly.
A lot of work
just for mustard.
Oh, it is.
All for lamb sausage.
All for the love
of mustard and sausages.
So,
we've made the mustard.
Now it is time
for the sausage.
We're gonna cut our bread
so we can fit
the merguez in there.
We're gonna
toast that bun.
We're gonna grab
a sausage.
FIERI: Onto the grill.
Onto the grill.
Look at that bad boy.
This is
the lamb sausage.
Moroccan spices, lamb,
a little pork.
We've got
our house-made mustard.
FIERI: Twice-blended.
The twice-blended
Dijon-style mustard.
We've got
our fig chutney.
And top it off with a little bit
of wild arugula.
Served with some pickles.
House-made?
House-made pickles.
Of course.
Whoa!
Got a little kick there.
Yep.
You need that chutney.
Now I understand
the chutney side of things.
You got a kick
from that sausage.
Mustard's perfect --
right on point.
But that sweetness
of the Mission-fig chutney
really comes in
and saves the day.
Otherwise, your palate would be
getting rocked.
Balance. Yeah.
Mmm. Nice bun.
That's a gourmet dog,
man.
Excellent. Nice job.
Thank you very much.
I need a lamb merguez.
I really thought
when I came down here
I was gonna get a great dog,
which I did.
Chicken sandwich is
out-of-bounds,
and the window show is
unbelievable.
Come with a sense of humor
and an open mind,
and it's great.
FIERI: Up next...
WILSON:
It goes in for a month.
A what?
A month.
We're headed
to Portland, Oregon...
Magic.
for old-school recipes...
Man has hash issues.
...treated
with some real respect.
Dig in with your
real military surplus
from World War II.
Actually,
that knife cuts.
I'm here in northwest
Portland, Oregon,
right by the industrial area.
Now, here's the idea --
You cruise
into an area like this,
and you find out where
the local workers are eating.
That's when you get
the real-deal grub,
and I hear one of those joints
is right here
at the Industrial Café
and Saloon.
Western
with sweet-potato fries up.
Pure comfort food.
Chipped beef
on toast.
It's not a fancy restaurant,
but you can come here anytime.
FIERI:
Before shift, noon whistle,
or even quitting time.
WOMAN: There's a lot
of manufacturing that goes on
right here
in the neighborhood.
Galvanizers,
heavy manufacturers.
FIERI: Guys like
Russ and Hawley Hubbard,
a father-and-son team who run
the shop across the street.
RUSS:
I am a builder/developer,
and we decided to build
apartments here,
and I thought,
"Well, this area needs
a nice restaurant."
FIERI:
So, in 2004, they took matters
into their own hands.
Russ built the joint.
Hawley machined the interior,
and Chef John Wilson created
a menu for hearty appetites.
It's pretty much all for
the working class around here.
FIERI: Which sticks
to their DIY attitude.
We make
all of our own food in-house.
We raise our own beef.
FIERI: What's the name
of the cattle ranch?
Lucky Tough Land
and Cattle.
[ Cow moos ]
FIERI: So it's no surprise
they build a corned-beef hash
from the ground up.
You make your own corned beef
for the corned-beef hash?
Yes.
Fire it up.
A little kosher salt.
Some curing salt, here.
It has maple syrup
and brown sugar in it.
Peppercorns.
Pickling spice.
Pickling spice itself.
Coriander.
Clove?
Yep.
Allspice.
A bunch of bay leaves.
Chili flakes.
And fresh garlic.
Gonna let this all simmer,
steep for how long?
For about an hour or so.
And we have a brisket.
We trim
a lot of the fat off.
We're gonna brine it?
Yes.
How long is it gonna
brine?
It goes in for a month.
A what?
A month.
FIERI: Then roast it off
in a 400-degree oven
for about two hours.
And now we're gonna begin
making our corned-beef hash.
Do it.
[ Machine whirring ]
I should try that.
Throw some potatoes
in here.
That's good corned beef.
[ Machine whirring ]
That's corned beef
dusted with potato.
Caramelized onions
and some peppers.
Green onions, roast garlic,
a little secret ingredient --
nutmeg.
You're taking hash
to another hash-alistic level.
Trying.
Salt and some ground pepper.
Now, is this gonna be cooked
on a flattop?
I have a special,
little hash pan
that I've been seasoning
over a few years, now,
so it's really nice --
getting nice and crispy.
Man has hash issues
if he's got
his own little,
special hash pan.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Nice crispiness on that.
Good-looking hash,
kid.
Whoo! Lookit!
Here they come!
Your favorite.
And there we go.
Oh, look!
[ Chuckles ]
Dude,
that's some good hash.
A little caramelized garlic
in there.
Yeah.
Roasted garlic in there.
So, you're getting
that texture.
It's not all corned beef.
Then you get the tenderness
of the onions
and the bell peppers,
a little bit
of the green onion.
Get that freshness.
And just enough potatoes
to legitimize it.
That's real-deal hash.
Nicely done.
And you know what made it?
That wicked
little skillet.
It's got a nice outer crust.
WOMAN:
You get the taste of the meat
without overpowering
everything else.
This showcases
the industrial area.
The steel's all around you.
This is your doing?
Yeah,
most of the steelwork here is.
We went into Dumpsters
and picked the gears up.
I would give him a sketch
and say, "Let's build it."
So, you're a Dumpster-diving,
restaurant-owning father
of a metal-working wizard?
Yes.
FIERI:
Add "lover of stick-to-your-ribs
food" to that list.
Chipped beef up.
And when we come back,
we're reconstructing
the classic working-man's meal.
That's one of the most
gourmet chipped beef
I think I've ever had.
FIERI:
We've got the Camaro parked
at the Industrial Café and
Saloon in northwest Portland,
a place that more than lives up
to its name.
Hash up.
Here, you've got
Chef John Wilson busy working
with the stick-to-your-ribs
dishes...
Western
with sweet potatoes.
...including one
that's a stand-out shout-out
to the working man.
Chipped beef up.
You don't see chipped beef
on toast very often.
FIERI: All right,
what are we on to now?
We're gonna slice up
our chipped beef here.
A locally sourced beef product
that's dry-aged, smoked.
It's smoky.
Okay, next up?
We're gonna make
the cream sauce for it.
A little oil here, shallots.
Get some chopped garlic.
Fresh rosemary.
Who's the tattoo?
It's my grandpa.
He got that exact tattoo
in World War II.
I like it.
Add our cream in here.
Let all those herbs steep
there in that cream.
Let it simmer
for about 20 minutes or so.
We got some roux.
And then after that's all done,
you're gonna strain that?
Yeah,
we strain it all out.
We got
our sourdough toast.
Got bubble magic
over there.
Just let all that cream sauce
soak up into that sourdough.
A little green.
That way, it's healthy.
Paprika.
Dig in
with your military surplus.
Real military surplus
from World War II.
Actually,
that knife cuts.
I'm stacking it up
for maximum shove-age.
How's it stack up?
It's great.
Chewiness
of the sourdough.
Nice little cream sauce.
Salty smoked beef.
Stick-to-your-ribs.
Yeah.
That's one of the most gourmet
chipped beef
that I think
I've ever had.
You should be proud
of that one.
Thank you.
It's got a nice, little
comfortable richness to it.
It's just one of my favorites.
I love it.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Brother,
this is a New York City bar.
I mean, this could be any club
in L.A. in a heartbeat.
It's not a rough,
redneck bar.
You find single women in here.
[ Chuckles ]
"You'll find single women
in here."
I love it.
So, that's it
for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Whistling ]
[ Laughter ]