I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Imitates siren ]
Plate it up.
Flavor jets.
...it's a one-stop shop
in the city by the bay.
Get in on that.
Come on. Release the jaw.
That's right. "Triple D"
the San Francisco way.
Show me the goods.
First up...
Fire up the chicken stock.
...an East Coast deli...
Do you have license
to matzo ball?
...serving up family recipes
from Baltimore.
I want to see a Guy Fieri
bite on this thing.
There you go!
Next, a stop
at a food-truck park...
And there's more.
...where one state-of-the-art
kitchen on wheels...
This is wild.
...is kicking out
killer Asian combos.
This right here is pretty odd,
but I like where you're going.
Then it's over
to the Mission area...
It is awesome.
...for some straight-up,
down-home Southern comfort.
Succulent.
Have I ever used that word
on "Triple D"?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here in beautiful
San Francisco, California.
Now, you've heard of
Fisherman's Wharf, right?
Okay, good,
'cause we're not going there.
We're going like 3/4 of
a mile south on Polk Street
to exactly what you'd expect
to find here in San Fran,
an East Coast deli.
This is Miller's.
I love
the corned-beef sandwich.
Get in on that. Come on.
Release the jaw.
Best pastrami I've ever had.
Big sandwich.
Like, bigger than my face.
I want to see a Guy Fieri bite
on this thing.
There you go!
The best deli
on the West Coast.
FIERI: 'Cause owner
Robby Morgenstein...
Could you get me
a pastrami Philly?
FIERI: ...comes from
a Baltimore bloodline
or blintzes and bagels.
My grandparents
were kosher caterers.
All of my cousins
have delis.
So when he started
this place in 2001,
his very loving mom handed over
all the family recipes,
including this deli classic...
I got the chicken-noodle soup
with matzo balls.
...that's been in Robby's family
for generations.
The matzo-ball soup
is delicious.
Matzo balls.
Do you have license
to matzo ball?
I got a grandmother
and a mother.
Okay.
God rest them.
Rose and Rae
made matzo balls.
Rose and Rae.
Fire up the chicken stock.
A little bit of olive oil.
Some mirepoix -- a couple
of big onions, celery, carrots.
A couple of big chickens.
Those are big. Those look like
San Francisco pigeons.
A big thing of parsley.
[ Whistles ]
A fistful
of peppercorns.
And some bay leaf.
A lot of water.
All right,
how long is this gonna go?
Come to a boil,
bring it down to a simmer --
about 90 minutes.
Strain it,
shred the chicken,
and while that's working,
we're going to --
Make some matzo balls.
Matzo meal, some salt,
a little bit
of white ground pepper.
You want to mix that up
real good.
That's all the dry.
Now you got all the wet.
So, for each cup of matzo meal,
you got four eggs.
1/4 cup of
schmaltz per cup.
So, what's the schmaltz
all about?
Schmaltz is flavored
chicken fat.
You're gonna
mix that together.
So, all the wet.
Look at this.
That's all she wrote.
So we let this set.
Then, after it forms up --
Just gonna take,
you know, an inch.
And how long
will they cook?
They're gonna cook
about 45 minutes.
A little bit of schmaltz.
Some mirepoix -- onions,
some carrots, some celery.
They're all nice
and sweated out.
We're gonna throw
the chicken stock on top
and then let it cook down
for about 30 minutes or so.
Now that's cooked down.
Now what?
Now we add fresh,
shredded chicken
from the stock
and then the matzo balls.
And then we get a little bit
of cooked egg noodles.
Let it get nice and hot.
And then we serve.
That's correct.
Word to the bird.
Ready?
Here we go.
One.
A little bit of stuff
on top.
[ Whistles ]
Boy, look at that.
Look how hearty that is.
Tender matzo balls.
That's the key right there.
Mmm.
Simple, to the point,
but I'll tell you something.
Out of the matzo balls
that I've had,
that is one tender, delicious,
flavorful matzo ball
with great chicken stock.
Well, thank you.
Matzo-ball soup.
Having been making matzo balls
for over 40 years myself,
this one's delicious.
MAN: I tell everybody
who's an East Coast transplant
they got to come here and try it
for themselves.
FIERI: 'Cause the menu's
chockful of East Coast flavors
with no West Coast compromise.
MAN #2: Everyone likes to
Californian-ize everything,
and Miller's is not California.
FIERI: Nothing's been lost
in translation,
whether it's the whitefish
platter,
the brisket french dip,
or this East Coast classic...
Potato Latke Delight.
...loaded with killer pastrami
and corned beef
that's shipped in from Detroit.
They're the best.
It's to die for.
So, a beautiful piece
of brisket here.
Pickled-corned-beef brisket.
And what are we gonna do
with it?
So, this puppy goes in.
And start it in some cold water
to cover.
We're just gonna simmer it off
for 3, 3 1/2 hours.
Some bay leaves,
a little bit of pickling spice.
A little more pickling spice.
No more salt.
It's already had the brine.
Cook this for 3 1/2 hours.
Transfer to the steam oven?
Yep.
All right, so, we're now
making the latkes.
A lot of
manufacturing potatoes,
all shredded up,
and a lot of eggs --
more than you would think.
And then a lot of onion.
Okay.
And then this is something
you got to do with your hands.
You get caught doing this
with your foot,
people are gonna tweak out.
That's probably true.
A little bit
of granulated garlic,
some onion powder, a good amount
of salt, black pepper,
and we're gonna mix
that up.
And then
just enough matzo meal.
If you put too much matzo meal
in, you got a puck of lead.
And that's it.
So, on the griddle.
[ German accent ]
On the griddle.
Now we scoop them out.
Nice big piles.
[ Normal voice ]
Cook them up on both sides?
You're gonna mark them
on both sides,
then we're gonna take them
to the deep fryer.
Show me the goods.
Pastrami.
Corned beef all cooked up,
ready to go.
We're just
gonna trim it up.
Grab your latkes.
Wow.
A couple of latkes.
Start on the point.
So, every time an order
comes out,
you're cutting it
to order?
We cut it to order.
How much do we give people?
A half-pounder?
Oh, easily.
This is more than that.
[ Whistles ]
And then the pastrami.
Get a nice pile of that.
Whoa!
A little bit of sour cream
and fresh applesauce.
Can I try this?
Go.
So, the proper method
of eating this
would be to --
You get a big chunk
of everything,
and then you dip it down
into the applesauce
and the sour cream.
Got it.
The latke is nice and crispy
but tender on the inside.
The corned beef is dynamite,
but the one that I really got
to try -- Wow.
That's some great pastrami.
That dude goes bananas.
Unh. Excellent job.
Thank you, man.
Really.
Dynamite.
Potato Latke Delight.
MAN: I'm never disappointed
with ordering it.
It's amazing.
MAN #2:
My mother makes good latkes,
but now Miller's latkes
are the standard.
Sorry, Mom.
I mean, here's the thing
I love about it.
It's using great product.
Scratch-making
the items you can,
and you have it
in a funky environment.
Feels like you're in
an East Coast deli.
I'm an East Coast deli guy.
Every bit.
FIERI: Up next...
Take me to Flavortown.
...we're headed to a food truck
that's parked in the heart
of town...
Wow.
Ooh, that's good.
...for a totally unique
Korean/Japanese concept.
This is something
I have not seen before.
The San Francisco food-truck
scene is alive and well.
I mean, they're corralling up
in food-truck parks like this,
and you never know what kind
of style and combination
you might discover,
like this funky truck,
where they've got Korean
and Japanese reinvented.
This is the KoJa Kitchen.
MAN:
Chicken kamikaze combo!
I've never come across anything
like this before.
MAN:
KoJa Kitchen for April.
Definitely nothing that you
would expect from a food truck.
MAN: Short-rib KoJa.
Kind of like a burger
but definitely not a burger.
FIERI: Stuffing Asian flavors
into a rice-cake bun
fits that description,
a crazy concept that Alan Tsai
came up with in 2011.
Then he convinced his buddies
Eric Thai, Mike Hayashi,
and Hip Leun
to go all-in on
a state-of-the-art truck.
I'm impressed, man.
I've seen some cool stuff
in my day, but this is -- Wow.
It's Korean/Japanese.
I'm having the short-rib KoJa.
Very unique, very original.
There's a rice patty
on the outside,
tender short ribs on the inside.
Absolutely delicious.
So, what are we gonna make?
Now we're making our signature
marinade for our short-rib KoJa.
Soy sauce, sugar --
a lot of sugar.
Some mirin.
Japanese cooking wine.
We got some sake.
Just a little bit of water.
I'm gonna power it up.
We're gonna boil it up
nice and easy.
Let it cool.
Now our next step?
We're gonna make
our root mixture.
And this is all part
of the marinade?
Yes.
Korean shingo pear.
This is something
I have not seen before.
It's kind of like papaya.
Okay.
Onions.
And we're gonna add some kiwis.
This right here
is pretty odd,
but I like
where you're going.
Add some garlic right in,
and we're gonna
fire this thing up.
Take me to Flavortown.
Now we're gonna combine it.
We're gonna add --
So that's our soy and our sugar
and the mirin and the sake.
And water.
Next, the fruit puree mix.
We're gonna add some lemon.
Fresh lemon juice.
Black pepper, sesame oil.
Mix it up.
Ooh, that's good.
These are toasted
sesame seeds.
Very nice.
Let's give it
a nice whisk.
And now we drop in
the meat.
We've got a nice short rib.
Mix this up,
give it a nice massage.
And we're gonna
marinate it overnight.
So, we've got our marinated
meat. Now what step?
We're gonna make the
garlic-seasoned rice buns.
We make it in these
custom-made aluminum press.
That's awesome.
First, we have to
oil the molds.
This is
a garlic-seasoned rice.
We're gonna oil the top,
as well,
just to make sure
it doesn't stick.
While I'm doing this --
Get it nice and flat.
There we go.
Let it cool
for about 5, 10 minutes.
And this is the patty that is
made in the KoJa burger?
Yes.
Awesome.
We're gonna put it
on the grill.
Ready to go.
We're gonna built a KoJa.
Check that just --
Ow, hot.
Plate it.
Some sesame slaw
on top of it,
a nice chunk of meat,
katsu aioli,
and our second patty.
Oh, the meat's
out of bounds.
You fold it up.
We're gonna put it in this
little pouch right here,
just nice presentation.
We add some more of the
katsu aioli on top of it.
A little bit of toasted
sesame seed.
Bite in.
It's outrageous.
The meat's out of bounds.
A little on the sweeter side,
not as spicy.
It's like a rice bowl
but not being in a bowl.
The little bit of lettuce
that goes along with it
is kind of like the vegetable
or the cabbage
that you would normally get
in a rice bowl.
The rice,
with its crunchy texture,
adds something you don't get
in a rice bowl.
This is Asian street food
at its best.
This is wow.
Mmm! Awesome!
Very savory.
A little spice to add
a little kick in it.
It has a great rice cake to it,
and the meat is tender.
I can't -- I'm speechless.
It's that good.
MAN:
Real-deal food.
The food and the people
and the truck --
I think it all comes together.
They've created something that
I've never seen anywhere else.
This is the only KoJa
that I know of in existence,
like, on the whole planet.
FIERI:
You did the truck right.
High-tech, putting
all these components --
These dudes are all that
and then some.
You guys are the bomb, man.
KoJa Kitchen --
You got to check them out.
Coming up, we're headed to the
southeast side of the Mission...
I like where this is going.
...for a Southern comfort spot
where the living's always easy.
It's not very good.
You should probably put it all
in the trunk of my car,
and I'll get rid of it
for you.
You have got to dig
San Francisco.
I mean, all the cool
little areas,
the neighborhoods,
the districts.
Well, here I am in the southeast
side of the Mission District
to check out a joint
that started in the '30s
as an Italian restaurant
in a garage.
Well, fast forward to 2006,
and now it's a funky
little joint
that's serving up some killer
Southern comfort food.
Oh, that's right.
You got to come kick it
at the Front Porch.
Table 7, Frito pie.
Bucket of chicken.
BOY:
The fried chicken is awesome.
This is my favorite restaurant.
Crawfish étoufée fries.
I know the food in my city.
And you say
that that is it.
This is the only game
in town.
FIERI: For honest to goodness
southern food,
thanks to friends
and business partners
Josey White and Kevin Kline.
We were always
talking about,
"This neighborhood needs
one more funky little joint."
This place became available,
and she gave me a call.
And the two partners brought in
comfort-food-cooking chef
Matt Marcus...
Mac and cheese, table 7.
FIERI: ...to introduce
down-home favorites
to the city by the bay,
like this Southern staple.
Shrimp and grits in the window!
My favorite thing on the menu.
Okay, what are we
gonna make first?
First,
we're gonna make grits
for our shrimp and grits.
We're gonna start
with whole milk...
...water...
Equal parts?
Equal parts.
And unsalted butter.
And we're gonna just
let this come to a boil.
And then we're gonna add
our stone-ground grits,
fresh-ground black pepper,
and plenty of kosher salt.
Grits need a lot of salt.
I agree with you.
So we'll let
these cook down.
Yep.
So, our grits have cooked
for 45 minutes.
The last thing we want to add
is sharp cheddar cheese.
[ Whistles ]
Next up, we're making?
Creole seasoning.
Start with kosher salt,
black pepper,
white pepper,
cayenne pepper...
[ Whistles ]
...paprika,
dark chili powder.
I like
where this is going.
We have coriander, cumin,
and last
is ground mustard.
And we just whisk this
all together.
And that's it.
Red-eye gravy.
Okay, so let's get into it.
We're gonna start
with some canola oil...
rough-chopped shallots.
A lot of them.
Garlic...
and andouille sausage...
a generous portion of our
creole spice that we just made,
and we're just gonna cook
this down a little bit.
We want those spices
to kind of toast.
So, from there, we're gonna add
Worcestershire sauce...
Tabasco.
A lot of it.
Well, it's called
"spicy shrimp and grits."
Hence.
We do
chicory coffee here...
and chicken stock.
That you make yourself,
of course.
Absolutely.
We're gonna bring it
to a boil,
let it simmer
for about 45 minutes.
So, now we're on to start
our shrimp and grits.
A generous ladle of the red-eye
gravy that we just made.
As if it's not
spicy enough,
we're gonna add a little bit
of our creole spice
and a little bit of butter.
And we're gonna add
our wild gulf shrimp.
And we're just gonna finish
poaching them
right in the red-eye
gravy here.
Soak up
all that great flavor.
I am dying to taste
that sauce.
So, I'd say
these guys are done.
[ Imitates siren ]
Plate it up.
Flavor jets.
All right, so we have
our nice creamy, cheesy grits.
We'll do our shrimp
right on top.
And the reduced red-eye gravy
with all the sausage and...
Fixin's.
...fixin's.
[ Gruff voice ] Then I put
the fixin's on there!
And last,
we have to add green onions.
And there you go.
[ Normal voice ] Let's just get
right into this right now.
This isn't exactly
how I know red-eye gravy
to be where I'm from,
but I will tell you
it is awesome.
Got a little coffee kick.
I mean, it's rich.
Grits are cheesy.
The andouille is spot-on.
Everything going on
in this is outstanding,
but really the crescendo
is those fresh shrimp.
I mean, succulent.
Have I ever used that word
on "Triple D"?
Oh, my gosh.
Killer dish.
Cool.
Glad you like it.
WOMAN:
The shrimp and grits.
The spicy shrimp
and grits were amazing.
The grits themselves
are great.
You can eat them with a fork,
which, to me, is the true test.
It's got that spicy sausage,
which I just wolfed down.
The Front Porch
makes you feel at home.
WOMAN #2:
I love the rocking chairs.
They remind you
of your childhood,
and you know if
there's a rocking chair,
you're gonna have
a rocking time.
FIERI:
And speaking of a good time,
we're giving you
a soda-soaked steak.
Dr Pepper short ribs.
FIERI:
Y'all come back now, you hear?
"Triple D" is at the Front Porch
in San Francisco's
Mission District,
where if rocking chairs
don't pull you in,
the rocking food will.
Dr Pepper short ribs.
They melt in your mouth.
They're absolutely awesome.
Dr Pepper?
Yeah! Let's do this.
All right,
so, we're gonna season
our boneless beef short ribs
with a little bit of salt
and fresh black pepper.
Super-hot sauté pan.
Canola oil.
And we want to get a nice sear
on these guys.
Sear-iously.
That's a good pun.
Thank you very much.
Now we're ready to start
the braise.
We're just gonna go straight
into a hotel pan here.
Mmm.
Smells great already.
We're gonna do mirepoix,
which is a rough chop of
carrots, celery, onion,
fresh thyme...
bay leaves...
chipotle peppers
in adobo sauce...
homemade chicken stock...
and then a lot
of Dr Pepper.
We don't call it Dr Pepper
short ribs for nothing.
[ Grunts ]
So, we just want to make sure
it's all covered.
In the oven how long?
350 for four hours.
All right, so we're ready
to plate up a short rib.
Take one of these guys.
In their own jus.
Yep.
We're gonna season this with
a little bit more black pepper.
A little more kosher salt.
Mount it with a little butter
at the end.
It's gonna help it
thicken up,
as if it's not already
rich enough.
It's just gonna make it
a little bit more rich.
So, we're just gonna let that
reduce back there.
All right, so, we have
celery-root puree.
A nice spoonful.
Beautiful.
Sautéed mustard greens,
our short rib,
and the Dr Pepper braise
right on top of that.
And last but not least,
a little fresh-grated
horseradish.
I love fresh horseradish.
It's not very good.
You should probably put it all
in the trunk of my car,
and I'll get rid of it
for you.
[ Chuckles ]
The short rib is so tender
that it's just falling apart.
You just have to help it
with the fork a little bit.
The celery-root puree
is a great medium
for the whole dish.
The fresh horseradish,
along with the mustard greens,
adds a nice contract
to this braising liquid
that's been reduced.
And the Dr Pepper is just this
nice round flavor and -- Mmm.
Every little piece
you did here -- killer.
Awesome. Thank you.
I mean really killer.
Cool.
And the Dr Pepper short ribs.
Juicy, it's tender,
and it's flavored amazing.
You can just take your fork
and just break it right apart.
It's just so soft.
FIERI:
Small, little kitchen,
and a chef with a lot
of personality.
It's awesome.
Cool. Thank you very much.
Enjoyed it.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Sorry. I forgot.
I have to cook
with my special friend here.
This is Eddie.
Wow.
This just went from fun
to really creepy.