I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That's the way to do it.
We're crossing the country...
Black-tar Texas tea.
...for some classic comfort.
I can't say it's good,
but I can say it's great,
though.
In Miami, Florida...
Fire it up.
...a blue-collar joint...
You look like you could've been
The Big Ragoo.
...serving up
some decadent dishes.
That is some awesome oxtail.
Then west of Park City, Utah...
Let's hit this, man.
...where a ski bum
takes a wild run...
That's one
of the weirdest dishes
I've ever seen on "Triple D."
...down a crazy trail
to Flavortown.
It is funky comfort.
I will give you that, brother.
And a few miles up the road...
[ Singing, German accent ]
Roll out the spaetzel.
...some cold-weather comfort...
Listen, you say "pork belly,"
I say "thank you."
...slope side.
Have you ever seen a place
at the bottom of a ski run
that has food like this?
No.
I rest my case,
your honor.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
So, I'm in Miami
in a very historic Art-Deco area
about 10 minutes
from South Beach,
and I'm here
to check out a joint
that is located in a...
wait for it.
Is it in a business park,
is it in a high-rise,
or is it in
a soon-to-be-remodeled hotel?
Hey, well, listen --
don't judge a book by its cover
'cause I hear this joint
is off the hook.
This is Blue Collar.
Shrimp and grits.
The best in Florida.
Everything packs
like an immediate flavor punch.
One of Miami's hidden gems.
FIERI: A reputation owner
Danny Serfer's had since 2012
when he started serving up
flavors locals love.
He's got Miami's palate
right on his little finger.
Oxtail on one.
MAN: The spicy oxtail
is a Haitian dish,
so it's not really traditionally
seen outside of Miami.
It just drips off the bone,
the juice is
in your mashed potatoes,
and you just suck it all up.
Fire it up.
Nice oxtail.
SERFER: People,
they go crazy about it.
Salt and pepper
those tails?
Always.
We're just gonna
brown them up real good,
get all
that caramelization going.
All right, next up.
Take them out.
Mmm.
You've got some nice
rendered fat down in there.
Now all that stuff, we're gonna
cook our vegetables in.
Carrots. Onion.
Boatloads of garlic.
Scotch bonnet. Celery.
Mango.
Mango?
It kind of tempers the heat
a little.
Thyme.
Salt and pepper.
We'll hit it with wine
and then just dump them back in.
Take these, cook them down
four to seven hours?
Yep.
Couple dollops
of our mashed potatoes.
"Dollops."
Some oxtail.
Oh, those really cooked down.
Look at that.
Yeah.
Little bit more
of the juice.
And then the bread
for dipping.
Chives.
Mmm.
You've got massive flavor,
but with
that little bit of spice
and that little bit of sweet
that you get on there -- dude.
Mmm.
Killer, man.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
That is awesome oxtail.
It kicked me in the mouth
just like it's an ox.
WOMAN:
This has very high-quality food
for an up-and-coming
neighborhood.
What this area is --
it's filled with young Miami.
We're not rich.
We're not famous.
So, we're trying
to find somewhere
that we can make our own.
FIERI:
And Danny's helping the cause
by giving the customers
a badge of honor
with a Blue Collar twist.
WOMAN: The regulars get
their own little time card
with their name.
It's like, you know, --
So, you're part of the club
once you have a time card.
I like it.
FIERI: And along
with the lunch-pail decor,
Danny's cooking up this
stick-to-your-ribs monster meal.
WOMAN:
Big Ragoo sandwich.
FIERI: A hot mess of cheese
and five kinds of meat.
I just go in for it
and just get messy.
You look like you could've been
The Big Ragoo.
SERFER:
First thing we're gonna do --
season our brisket.
Just add a little bit of oil
to get it going.
You're gonna sear it
on both sides,
and it's nice to do things
in one pot.
One pot. Builds flavor.
Same thing
with the pork shoulder?
Yep.
Season it up,
fat-side down.
All right.
Pork is nice and brown.
Locally made sausage.
Italian?
Yep.
Pancetta?
This is
some veal shoulder.
Love that.
Salt and pepper.
All kinds of flavor
down in that pan.
We'll render that down
a little bit
and then start cooking
the rest of our vegetables.
Onions.
Whole garlic.
That's the way to do it.
Chili flake.
Pepper. Salt.
Tomato?
Yep.
This is a San Marzano.
I love
where this is going.
Now we're gonna start
adding everything else back in.
And add a little bit
of water.
Tell me
that's corn starch slurry.
It's just milk.
Really?
I learned it from, like,
an old Italian person.
The lactose in the milk is
gonna help break down the meat,
and it's gonna help it
pull apart and shred up.
I'm gonna go try that
just because of that.
All right,
how long is this gonna simmer?
Six, seven hours.
Then we're gonna kind of
treat it like a pulled pork,
and we're just gonna
rip it apart with our tongs.
Hit it with a little bit
of tomato sauce.
That's a nice
seeded hoagie roll.
And you see that nice little,
salty provolone?
Now into the oven.
Let the cheese melt.
Are we ready?
Yep.
That's ridiculous.
It's way big.
Mmmmmmm.
There is so much flavor.
You got a little bit of spice
in there -- very rich.
The awesome,
awesome bread.
Look at that -- you got
little bits of sausage in there,
little bits of the veal.
That sharp provolone
coming through
with the saltiness
on top.
I would die to have that
over pasta.
Come back for dinner.
[ Scoffs ]
Oh, my God,
that's a good-looking Ragoo.
That is a Ragoo.
This sandwich, oh, my gosh.
It's almost like you're eating
a delicious lasagna,
but with, like,
much better meat.
So, these are some friends
of mine, the Fox family.
You've been to a bunch of
"Triple D" joints, haven't you?
Yes.
What do you think
of this place?
Great.
It's one of the best.
Well done, my friend.
Thanks.
Awesome.
FIERI:
Coming up, we're road tripping
to Park City, Utah...
Let's hit this, man.
...for a hardcore skier's
turn...
I mean, you're funky, bro.
You're daring.
...on some righteous dishes.
That's like a $10 lift ticket
to Flavortown.
I'm here at Prospector's Square
at Park City, Utah,
and I'm right
in the thick of things.
Let's see -- half mile that way,
Park City Mountain Resort.
About a mile that way,
Deer Valley.
I'm here to check out a joint
where a local boy slash ski bum
has a motto of "Gourmet Food
at Local's Prices."
This is Sammy's Bistro.
When you come to Sammy's,
you get a home-cooked meal.
Steak sandwich and fish tacos
in the window.
You could spend
a lot more money in town,
but you won't get better food.
FIERI: That was the idea
for Chef and owner Sam Harris
who opened this joint in 2011
for his compadres,
which means
ski pants and hat hair
are definitely expected.
Do you ski?
Do you board?
Oh, I'm a skier.
Very nice.
I competed at Moguls
back in the day.
That could explain
Sammy's freestyle approach
in the kitchen.
I put a bunch of ideas
into a manilla envelope
when we were starting up
the restaurant,
and I just
pulled stuff out.
I had probably
100 to 200 ideas.
The pulled pork
is one of my favorites.
My go-to
is the mahimahi fish taco.
FIERI:
And then there's the creation
that sounds like a bunny hill...
Savory chicken bowl.
FIERI: ...but rocks
black-diamond flavor.
It's got the chicken and then
that wonderful cilantro dressing
and then the crunch
of the tortillas.
HARRIS:
Savory chicken bowl.
Show me what you've got.
Little canola oil.
Poblano.
And onions.
Put a little garlic in
and then the chicken
and then coat it
with spices.
Yellow curry.
Garam masala.
Paprika.
This is onion powder.
Salt.
And a little black pepper.
So, get the spices
coating the chicken,
and then just hit some water
on top.
Let it simmer
for two to three hours.
Until it's super tender.
Super-tender
pulled chicken.
Okay,
so the chicken's cooked.
Now we put
the bowl together?
Yep.
Some tortilla strips.
Jasmine rice.
We ladle our chicken.
Some of the tortilla strips
on top.
Make it tall.
Cilantro.
And finish off
with the tomatillo aioli.
You don't wear a helmet
when you ski, do you?
I have to now.
My fiancée makes me.
That's one
of the weirdest dishes
I've ever seen
on "Triple D."
You just throw
something together.
Sometimes it turns out.
So, this one is one of those.
There we go.
How do I eat it?
Just mash it up.
Make it happen.
Try to get a little bit
of everything.
Chicken's super tender.
It almost turns
into a jambalaya
crossed with some crazy
Indian dish I've never had.
Comfort food at its finest,
you know?
It is funky comfort.
I will give you that,
brother.
Mmm.
How much is this?
10 bucks.
It's like a $10 lift ticket
to Flavortown.
MAN: Savory chicken bowl
with rice.
It's comfort in a bowl.
That's why
I love this place.
It's super comfortable.
It's like
being in a Jacuzzi.
Time out.
So, we're in a Jacuzzi
right now?
Pretty much.
Sammy's is a place
where the locals go.
It's almost like "Cheers."
You walk in
and you always know somebody.
FIERI:
But when it comes to the menu,
he definitely heads
way out of town.
The Chivito club.
The who club?
Who's Chivito?
Chivito is a sandwich
from Uruguay.
Let's hit this, man.
We're gonna make the marinade
for the pork tenderloin --
canola oil...
soy sauce...
garlic...
ginger...
cilantro...
fresh limes.
And how long is this tenderloin
gonna marinate?
Oh, we usually do
45 to an hour.
Grill it.
Yep.
Medium-rare? Medium?
Medium.
And let it rest
for a minute.
And while we do that,
we're gonna make the egg.
Hey, hey!
He'll be here all week, folks.
Slice it thin.
And then
it's on a hoagie roll.
So, we have a little bit
of the tomatillo aioli,
lettuce, tomato,
pork tenderloin,
and little bit of bacon
and some spicy mayo.
All right,
and the egg is missing.
[ Laughter ]
Where's the egg?
That's the good question.
Looks good.
Let's have it.
Hey, it's perfect now,
right?
There it is.
Throw a little fried egg on top.
Little more
tomatillo aioli.
Can't get enough
of that sauce.
No, you can't.
Good-looking fries.
Here is
our chivito club.
The seasoned pork
has way more flavor
than I anticipated
with the garlic and the ginger.
But I really think
that the kicker
is that
tomatillo-cilantro aioli.
Even with egg on there,
it's a great sandwich.
I mean,
you're funky, bro.
You're daring.
You're like that.
Make it happen --
That's my mantra.
Nicely done, bro.
Thanks, man.
The pork is very tender.
It's like breakfast and lunch
all at the same time.
MAN:
The taste is gourmet.
The prices are reasonable.
You could be
from out of town visiting
and you're gonna feel like
you're part of Park City.
Watch out for this guy.
When you see him
on the slopes,
if he skis like he cooks,
take a day off.
FIERI: Up next...
Boom, boom, mushroom.
...we're staying at Park City
and heading slope side...
Wow! At a ski resort.
...where a hidden joint...
You've got sweet and heat
on meat you can't beat.
...is blowing up
the after-ski action.
Mexican, Texan, Southern combo
with a twist -- elevated.
Really easy to explain.
I'm here at Park City, Utah,
at the Silver Star Village,
which is right at the base
of Park City Mountain Resort.
Now, I know that's a mouthful,
but I want you
to find this place
'cause I hear
they're doing way more
than you'd find
at your average ski lodge.
This is the Silver Star Café.
Got a sea bass
and osso bucco for 112.
The best place to eat
in Park City -- bar none.
And braised short rib.
MAN: There really is something
that makes this place
special in Park City,
and it's Jeff and Lisa.
FIERI: That would be veterans
of the local food biz
Jeff and Lisa Ward.
I've been doing restaurants
in town for a long time.
We've never owned one ourselves.
We took the plunge.
FIERI: That was in 2010
when they took over this joint
at the bottom
of the Silver Star chair lift.
We're a local joint,
but we resonate with
the destination visitor.
FIERI:
Thanks to an eclectic menu
cooked up by Chef Dave Bible.
Comfort food
brought to a higher level.
It's familiar,
but with some twists to it.
I have the pork osso bucco.
Pork osso bucco
with tomatillo salsa --
Mexican Italian.
The first thing we're gonna make
is the roasted-tomatillo salsa.
Start off with some oil
in the pan.
Chopped onions...
tomatillos...
poblano chilies...
salt...
pepper.
We'll cook these
for about 20 minutes.
All the vegetables are cooked.
Add chicken stock.
It's a roasted chicken stock,
and I used tomato paste.
You kind of get
like a brown --
I got you.
Then just Burr mix it.
The tomatillo salsa's
done now.
Now we're gonna start
our pork shanks.
First thing I'm gonna do
is season them.
Lots of salt and pepper.
That's pretty important.
Little bit of oil
in the pan.
Throw a little vegetable on here
so these will roast
at the same time
as the pork browns.
And then I place the pork.
And we're gonna roast these off
in the oven at what temp?
Right about 560 degrees.
About seven
or eight minutes.
So, we're done
being roasted?
Yes, sir.
So, I'm gonna place them
into the pan.
Put the veg in the pan.
Homemade chicken stock?
Yep.
Foil this back up.
Put it back in the pizza oven?
Yes, sir, for three hours.
It's like
Christmas morning.
I'm gonna go ahead
and plate it.
So, I've got
these chipotle grits --
yellow grits
spiked with chipotle.
My middle name's
chipotle grit.
Very nice.
Gorgeous.
Load one of the shanks
on there.
Got the tomatillo salsa.
Already hot. Ready to roll.
Just a little garnish
of queso fresco,
just a little bit
of chopped cilantro.
And there we are -- That's
the pork osso bucco with
roasted-tomatillo salsa.
Outrageous.
Nice acidity
in the tomatillo salsa.
Pork's fall-apart tender.
Love the poblano note.
The grits...
pull you into it.
Good Mexican, Texan,
Southern combo
with a twist --
elevated.
Really easy to explain.
Chef, great energy.
Great food. Nice job.
Appreciate that.
Thank you very much.
Wow! At a ski resort.
Pork osso bucco.
WOMAN: It absolutely melts
in your mouth.
It's really,really good.
And it's a cozy,
wonderful atmosphere in here.
FIERI: Which fits right in
with the food.
MAN:
I like the mushroom stroganoff
if I'm really hungry
after a day of skiing.
Bunch of different mushrooms.
It's delicious.
Okay, so, we're gonna be
making the spaetzel
for the vegetarian
mushroom stroganoff.
Love me some spaetzel.
We'll start off
with the flour.
We're gonna sift it
a bit.
Create a little hole there,
toss in the eggs,
little warmed milk --
not boiling --
a little bit of water,
and a little salt.
I'm gonna start working it
with my hands.
Doesn't take very long
at all.
You want a really nice,
sticky dough.
I've got a spaetzel maker
over here.
[ German accent ]
♪ Roll out the spaetzel ♪
All right, dough's done.
We're just gonna take it
into this little scoopy thingy.
Gravity will eventually
do its job.
So, you just slide it
into the boiling water
back and forth.
The sliding action will actually
cut the dough as it goes in.
A lot of people refer
to spaetzel as pasta.
It's actually
more of a dumpling.
Now, it needs to cook in here
for just a couple minutes.
And we just put it
in an ice bath.
And then we sauté it
at the time of service.
Got it.
Fire up the pan.
Little bit of oil.
Then I got ahead and dump in
my sliced, domestic mushrooms.
So, the buttons?
Yep.
The oysters.
Here's the shiitakes.
Okay.
A little salt and pepper.
All right,
then I just stir it.
This will get cooked down
for about 25 minutes or so.
So, now we're gonna assemble
the dishes.
So, we're gonna get
a little oil in the pan,
little bit of red onion.
Touch of garlic.
Mushrooms.
Little toss.
Those cook
just a moment or two.
One of the keys to this
is the roasted-vegetable stock.
Add a little bit of sour cream
right off the bat.
Sort of swirl that in.
That's where you kind of get
that classic stroganoff flavor.
Chives. Salt. Pepper.
And now we're gonna go
for the reduction.
We're gonna be plating
the spaetzel.
Next is the mushrooms.
Put just a touch more
sour cream,
then a little bit of chive.
There you go.
And that is the vegetarian
mushroom stroganoff.
Boom, boom, mushroom.
Little mix.
I can't say it's good.
[ Fork clatters ]
But I can say it's great,
though.
The type of mushrooms,
the way you cook them down
but leave them with integrity --
I think that the mushrooms
are still tender enough.
They brought out tons
of flavor.
I think that stock
plays a huge role in it.
It's hearty.
It's comforting.
Outrageous.
You're a gangster.
Thank you, sir.
Tastes like
you're in Germany somewhere,
and it's perfect when you come
right off the slopes.
I was gonna leave, but between
the slopes, the snow,
and the dude that made
the awesome mushroom stroganoff,
I got to stick around.
You got another dish?
I have a crispy pork belly.
When we come back,
hanging out
at the Silver Star Café
in Park City, Utah.
Love me some pork belly.
Me, too.
Uh, welcome back.
It's the "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives,"
not "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and ski slopes."
I'm hanging out
at the Silver Star Café,
and you have promised me
if I would come back
and not go out there,
you said we could have...
Crispy pork belly.
Mmm!
All right, bring it.
First thing I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna score the meat.
The next thing I'm gonna do
is smear molasses on it.
Black-tar Texas tea.
Next, I'm gonna season it.
And just one side?
Just the fat side?
Yeah.
Just salt and pepper.
Real liberal on this one.
Just throw it on the pan.
We're gonna toss it
in the pizza oven
for about seven or eight
minutes.
Just put
a little roast on it?
Little bit of crunch
on it,
and now we're gonna braise it.
Right.
So, I start off
with maple syrup in the pan.
I'll just place this
right on top of that syrup.
Now, you take
the cinnamon-amon-amon-amon.
Just throw it on top.
And your water, doctor.
Yep.
Three hours.
Plastic and foil.
Plastic really locks down,
and you actually build steam
in this,
and if you poked it,
it would pssssh!
A sheet of foil.
And then after this
is all covered and sealed up,
it'll go in the oven
right around 560 degrees or so
for about three hours.
After that,
we actually let it cool
in its braising jus
overnight.
Then we'll cut it.
Then it'll get skewered.
And then what? Fried?
Fried.
So, this is the crispy
pork belly appetizer.
So, you start off with
your cooked beans and apple.
Look at that!
Okay, you think that's enough
pork belly?
You gave me half a pig.
And then the last thing
that we're gonna do,
it's my own interpretation
of a Carolina-style
barbecue sauce,
and then finish off
with a touch of green.
That is
the crispy pork belly.
Listen, you say "pork belly,"
I say "thank you."
Look at that pork
just falling apart.
You get that molasses
right off the bat.
Carolina-style sauce...
with that vinegar
is right there.
You got sweet and heat
on meat you can't beat.
[ Laughter ]
Crispy pork belly and taco.
Have you ever seen a place
at the bottom of a ski run
that has food like this?
No.
Yourself?
I rest my case, your honor.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
What is that?!
What is that type of
ridiculousness?
Does this go on all the time?
[ Laughter ]
That's awesome!
[ Laughs ]