Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
This is funky.
...we're doing
a little chilling...
I'll be here all week.
...and some
serious grilling...
It's gonna be a fat day.
...in Orange County,
California.
That is killer.
A fresh take
on a food truck...
Look how beautiful
that sandwich is.
...firing up
some macho Mexican.
That's it. I got to go.
I can't handle tortas
and chilaquiles in the same day.
Then a funky joint
in Miami, Florida...
This is gonna be weird.
...smoking full-flavored hog...
That is outrageous.
...with a tiny twist.
Winner, winner,
pig-wing dinner.
And on the island
of Oahu...
This is
your work environment?
...it's a grillapalooza...
Probably
the crispiest chicken
that anybody will ever try
that has not been fried.
...turning out
real-deal Hawaiian.
The true Oahu
Huli Huli chicken Mike way.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here
in Orange County, California,
and I'm looking
for a taco truck.
Now, before you start rolling
your eyes, listen to this story.
I hear
it's a husband-and-wife team
where they're all about
sustainability,
farm-to-table, and organics,
and the Mexican food
is off the hook.
This is Tamarindo --
scratch-made comida Mexicana.
Chilaquiles, drunken torta.
The food is amazing.
Just blows me away.
FIERI:
It's like Mexican food
with a California freshness,
kind of?
WOMAN: You can tell
they locally source everything.
It's reflected in the food.
It has to do
with Sarah and Pedro.
FIERI: That would be
Sarah and Pedro Resendiz,
who have been running this truck
since 2011.
Fish taco.
Best story you ever hear
in the restaurant business.
It's where the line cook meets
the beautiful waitress,
and they go off
and get married
and open up
their own restaurant joint.
That's the story.
Drunken.
Drunken. Heard.
I am diehard drunken-torta fan.
Flank steak
marinated in Dos Equis.
With all kinds of goodness
in there -- excellent.
What are
we gonna make first?
We're gonna start
with the marinade
for the drunken torta.
Gonna start with the onions.
Okay.
Garlic.
Oranges.
Soy sauce.
A little salt and pepper.
And the cerveza.
All right, so,
we're gonna do flank steak.
And we let that marinate
for how long?
Overnight.
And we're gonna
grill the steak now.
We're gonna
caramelize our onions.
A little bit of vegetable oil,
salt and pep.
Cook that for about
three, four minutes.
A little cola.
You glaze them
with a little cola?
Yes, sir.
I like it.
These are
our bolillo rolls.
They came
from the Mexican bakery.
Garlic beans.
A little bean spread
on there.
Both sides.
It's a little natural mayo.
You'll just toast them
on there?
The steak is ready to go.
Okay.
Put it back
on the flat-top.
Queso fresco.
Got it.
Bolillo's ready.
Put that on top.
Some of those onions
right there.
Herbal salsa.
Mm.
Local tomatoes.
Organic arugula.
I don't see a lot of arugula
in Mexican food.
Cut it right in half.
And that's all she wrote.
Drunken torta, right there.
Let me know
what you think.
Look how beautiful
that sandwich is.
Here's the deal.
I got to be honest.
I don't like it.
Fair enough.
I love it.
This is an orchestra
of flavors.
The meat has great flavor --
really nice and tender.
You get a little bit
of the citrus,
a little bit
of that acid coming through.
The bean spread on there
working as the natural mayo --
outrageous.
But the kicker here, baby,
grilled onions
with the cola deglazing.
Without question the best tortas
I've ever had in the States.
Thank you.
That's killer.
MAN:
I mean, how can you go wrong
when it's meat marinated
in beer?
You will travel to wherever
they are to have this.
Yep.
How far have you had to drive
to come and find them?
Oh, my gosh, 32 miles.
About two hours to get up here.
Enjoy.
Where did you learn
how to cook?
Mostly from my mom.
You know, I was like
5 years old, sitting, you know,
next to my mom,
watching her cooking.
So you learned
a bunch of this in Mexico,
and then you came
to the States.
Yeah, I was that kid,
you know.
That's what I love.
I just love food.
Chilaquiles for Kim.
WOMAN:
I'm having the chilaquiles.
It's made
with a fresh tomatillo sauce,
and it just makes
every bite magical.
Now we're gonna make
the chicken chilaquiles.
That's it. I got to go.
I can't handle tortas
and chilaquiles in the same day.
Gonna start with the marinade
for the chicken.
Achiote paste.
Chipotle chilies.
And adobo. Got it.
Vegetable oil.
The roasted garlic.
Black pepper.
Mexican oregano.
Lime juice.
Salt.
And water.
So, this is
our achiote marinade.
[ Whistles ]
Got a nice kick
to it, right?
Love it.
And for that,
we're gonna use organic chicken.
Thighs or breasts?
Thighs.
Season it
with salt and pep.
And how long
will we let this marinate?
Overnight.
Now let's move on
to cooking the chicken.
While that's cooking,
we're gonna start
with frying our chips.
Frying pan for our egg.
For our what?
Organic and local eggs.
Season it
with a little salt.
These babies are gonna go
into our tomatillo salsa.
Chicken's ready.
Tortilla chips.
Now we're getting some
of this achiote chicken.
FIERI: Look at that.
Screw it up
with the egg on there.
Let's put some more salsa.
Mexican crema.
Cotija cheese.
Cilantro.
Gorgeous.
Chef,
this is really amazing.
This tomatillo salsa
with the crema
and the tender chicken
and the chips fried
just the right way...
It's tangy, it's spicy,
and it's handmade.
This is righteous, man.
Amazing. Delicious.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
Love the chilaquiles.
You can't go wrong with it.
WOMAN: You just leave
with that little burn in your
mouth that's not too much.
It's just perfect.
WOMAN: Nothing compares
to Sarah and Pedro's
delicious Tamarindo truck food.
You're just making it happen.
Uh-huh. Totally.
That's beautiful.
Awesome.
Chef, nice to meet you.
Thank you very much.
Congratulations.
FIERI: Coming up...
I mean,
this is ridiculous.
...in Miami, Florida...
That's some of the best pork
I've ever had, honestly.
...a laid-back joint dishing out
a taste of Texas.
This is a chili experience.
So, I'm here in Miami.
Now, this is called
the Mimo District.
I'm about a half mile
from South Beach, Miami,
and this is one of the largest
art-deco areas that they have.
Now, back in the '30s and '40s,
this place was rocking.
It was like Miami Vegas.
Well, they've gone
through the good times
and the bad times,
but not to worry.
They're on their way back
because of a bunch
of really cool restaurants
and unique shops,
and one of the joints
that's leading the way
is right here at The Federal.
Fried chicken, ready, pick-up.
When you want good food,
you come to The Federal.
The venison chili
and grit fries.
It's completely unique.
The flavors are amazing.
There's a lot of love
and passion into the food.
FIERI: Just part of the "do
what you love" attitude
of Colombian-born chef
Cesar Zapata.
Got tired of working in hotels
doing the corporate thing.
I just want
to do my own thing.
So he did, with his wife,
Ani Meinhold, in 2012.
They opened The Federal, and
it's been craziness after that.
So, where did you learn
to cook?
Texas.
From doing barbecue? Is that
where the smoker's coming from?
Barbecue
is standing right outside.
The smoking is happening
right where you walk past.
I haven't eaten meat
for 40 years,
but when I come to The Fed,
I make a major exception,
and I eat the pig wing.
Buffalo-style pig wing.
It's like, basically,
the Buffalo chicken wing.
This is funky.
We get them from a farm.
They raise pigs
that have wings.
Shut up.
[ Laughs ]
What is this?
Like, a mini shank.
It's from this part,
right here, from the pig.
Basically,
they're, like, poached.
Then, what we do is
that we smoke them.
Oh.
And how long
are those gonna go on?
They're gonna go there
for maybe 20, 30 minutes.
Just enough to perfume them
a little bit,
put a little bit
of color to them.
What kind of smoke was that?
A little bit of hickory
and beech.
We're gonna make the
Buffalo sauce for the pig wings.
Let's get it going.
Texas Pete hot sauce
as a base.
Garlic powder,
ginger powder, chipotle,
apple-cider vinegar,
Sriracha, Florida honey.
We whisk.
Holy butter, Batman.
One pound. And then we start
to emulsify the butter.
And we'll bring
the pig wings back in.
We're gonna make
the seasoned flower.
All-purpose, garlic powder,
ginger, onion powder, chipotle.
That's definitely Texas.
Salt, black pepper. Mix.
Just the natural moisture
that's on there --
the flour adheres
to that.
Now,
this is the buttermilk.
Dry, wet, dry.
Over to the fryer.
Canola oil.
350?
So, here's the pig wing,
brushed with a little bit
of house Buffalo sauce.
And bleu-cheese mousse.
Did you dress the carrots
with anything? Vinaigrette?
A little house vinaigrette.
I mean,
this is ridiculous.
The shank, the smoke.
The wing sauce
doesn't overpower it.
It doesn't steal the show.
The crunch
at the end of it. Oh.
That is outrageous.
That's some of the best pork
I've ever had.
It's a winner, winner,
pig-wing dinner.
Excellent.
And if this is a representation
of the rest of the menu,
it's gonna be a fat day.
The pork wing.
Unbelievable.
It's not too spicy. It's not
like it overpowers the meat.
It is so, so tasty.
We had very innovative,
unique dishes.
The grit fries are the best.
MAN:
Venison chili and grit fries.
It's amazing.
We're gonna make venison chili.
Start with some canola oil.
Farm-raised ground venison.
From Texas.
Okay.
Gonna get this browned.
Smoked brisket?
Smoked brisket.
White onions, poblano peppers,
and then we mix this.
Sweat them down.
Probably for two minutes.
Then we add the chili paste.
Gonna cook that chili paste,
like, for seven minutes,
until it starts
to get a little dark.
We add garlic.
Comino?
Comino.
A little beer --
Make sure we taste.
How is it?
Oh, it's good.
That's right.
Wow, that's dark.
Chicken stock.
A little salt, season.
Black pepper.
Cook this for two hours
until it starts
to thicken a little bit.
Now we add
the cilantro bouquet.
And then we'll let that sit
for 15, 20 minutes.
What is it served with?
Some grit fries.
So, we're gonna make grits,
and then we're gonna make fries
out of them?
Exactly.
This is gonna be weird.
Florida milk.
Stone-ground grits.
We mix this.
A little black pepper,
Cajun seasoning, salt.
Let this cook down.
And once they start
to become a little bit stiff,
we're gonna add
the butter,
and then we're just
gonna emulsify it.
Next up.
Cheese -- jack.
Ready.
Now, we'll take these onto
a sheet tray, let them cool.
And then we're just gonna
slice them into logs.
Into the fryer?
In the fryer.
Nice and golden-brown.
Look at that.
This is gangster.
Then we got the chili.
Mexican crema.
Cotija cheese.
Scallion love.
Chipotle.
And that's it.
Mm. That is ridiculous.
Thank you.
This has the depth,
the richness, the complexity.
It's not super-spicy.
Chili shouldn't blow
your head off.
Then you get to the finale,
this grit fry.
It's got that crunch, and you
got the cheese coming through.
This is
a chili experience.
Like a little symphony.
This is like the philharmonic.
Outstanding.
Very nice, Chef. Fantastic.
Thank you very much.
ZAPATA:
Venison chili, ready.
It's really good.
You get a little sweet,
a little spicy.
The crunch is awesome.
The place is funky, the staff
is cool, and the food is legit.
You are a remarkable chef.
Big props, man.
Thank you.
Up next,
in Kaneohe, Hawaii...
Oh!
...a grilling guru...
Mike's the man.
You got to come see him.
...setting up roadside...
It's what you got to love about
coming to the islands, man.
...and inspiring more
than just a love of food.
Will you marry me?
So, I'm here
on the beautiful island of Oahu,
and I'm right on the border
between Kaneohe and Kahaluu,
and I'm right on the edge
of the Kaneohe Bay.
[ Exhales sharply ]
Why would I go through
such a tongue twister?
Well,
for a very specific reason.
You see, I have driven
by this place over 100 times,
and this is the place
that inspired me
to get my own
Huli Huli-chicken machine.
This is the original
Mike's Huli Huli Chicken.
Two char siu pork plates
ready to go.
MAN: I love it.
You can't really go anywhere
else to get this kind of stuff.
FUSE: Here,
half-chicken plate here.
WOMAN:
Said, "What is that smell?"
I said, "Husband,
you got to turn back around."
Hey, char siu plate
with mac salad.
Everybody knows Reno,
the chef here on the island.
This where I bring
all my haole family to.
Every time my haole friends
come down from the mainland,
I always bring them to
Uncle Mike's Huli Huli Chicken.
This guy
rocks the house, huh?
It's great.
FIERI: This guy is owner
and Oahu native Mike Fuse...
Yeah, I got two
Huli chickens ready to go.
FIERI: ...who's been
putting his own mark
on the traditional Hawaiian
Huli Huli recipe since 2010...
MAN: It's slow-roasted.
It's got a very smoky flavor,
very juicy.
FIERI: ...thanks to his
custom wood-fired rotisserie
that keeps juices on the inside
without burning the outside.
So, I've always said,
since I started doing
Huli Huli chicken,
that one day, I would come back
and recognize the man
that showed me
the first way how to do it.
I want you to give everybody
the rundown,
the true Oahu
Huli Huli chicken Mike way.
You got to first of all
get 2 1/4 to 3 pounds.
Not too big of a bird.
Got it.
Then you cut it
down the center.
Okay.
Then we brine it
in Hawaiian sea salt.
A little lemon juice, too.
That's it.
Just for taste. That's it.
So, we'll let the chicken
brine how long?
Overnight.
And what's our next step?
Gonna make the rub?
Yeah.
We got a little salt, paprika,
little bit of cumin,
pepper, garlic powder,
oregano,
a little bit
of white pepper...
Onion.
And what's this down here,
a little chili?
That's cayenne pepper.
A little cayenne. Okay.
Okay, then we go ahead
and mix it up.
Put it all, rub it in.
Just turn and burn.
Yep, turn and burn.
Then you get
the chicken here, and...
It's got to go
through the thighs
and the top
of the wings, right?
And the top
of the wings, right,
because if you don't get it
on tight, what happens?
One part starts
to come off,
and it starts dragging
into the fire
and gets burnt up
and falls off.
Charcoal-crusted chicken.
Not a big specialty here
at Mike's.
All right, so,
we're ready to go?
Grab my hook.
Cantilever that out.
Yep.
Okay.
Okay, pull that up.
And over we go.
Over to the fire.
FUSE:
Okay. Put that down.
Get it going.
FIERI:
And how long, Mike?
About 40 minutes, depending
on how hot the fire is.
And what kind of wood
are we using?
This is kiawe wood.
Kiawe?
Yeah. It burns very hot.
It's like mesquite.
Hawaiian mesquite.
Hawaiian mesquite, right.
Got it.
All right, so, what we do is
we just grab this chicken here,
pull that off the fire.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that, man.
Take the chickens off.
Okay,
and take that one off.
And cut the chicken
down the center.
So soft it's falling apart
already.
And we add
some macaroni salad, here.
Pineapple.
Go ahead and put the whole
half chicken on there.
And Mike's secret sauce.
Dude,
I am telling you what.
This is even better
than I remember it.
Oh!
The skin is so juicy.
Probably
the crispiest chicken
that anybody will ever try
that has not been fried.
Look at that.
Good stuff, huh?
It's so legit.
It's what you got to love about
coming to the islands, man.
Okay, I got
two half-Huli-chicken plates
with the secret sauce
ready to go.
I love the chicken.
It's very tender, juicy.
It has that smoky taste.
And "bird"
isn't the only word here.
Mike also puts a spin on pork...
Roadside dining, baby,
at its finest.
...when we come back.
Right now,
"Triple D" is hanging loose
on the island of Oahu
at Mike's Huli Chicken,
an open-air joint
firing up the goods
in the middle of paradise.
This is
your work environment?
This is it, man.
You turn to one side, you got
the mountains all around you,
and you got
the ocean right there.
And people just smell it
when they come by.
That's it.
That's why we have it
on the side of the road, man.
It's just a nice, cool, easy,
relaxing place
to enjoy your meal.
Two char siu pork plates
ready to go.
WOMAN:
The pork is awesome.
It's got a great flavor.
The meat's real tender.
Okay, we're gonna make
the char siu park, okay?
Okay, we got
a 3- to 4-pound pork butt.
Boneless, skinless pork.
Boneless, skinless pork,
yeah.
And what we do is we cut it
down the center like so.
Okay. And what does "char siu"
stand for?
Red Chinese pork.
Okay, now what we have here
is two cups of soy sauce.
A little hoisin.
Oyster sauce.
A little bit
of Chinese five-spice, okay?
Got it.
And brown sugar --
about six cups, yeah?
And red food coloring,
but this is optional,
but I like it red.
Okay.
About a tablespoon of that.
Okay, set the pork in.
And that's all she wrote.
That's all she wrote.
See how red?
Beautiful.
Nice and beautiful red.
Looks just like
in the Chinese restaurants.
And just let that
marinate all the way in.
Exactly. Overnight.
We ready?
Ready.
We're gonna skewer these pork,
here, like so.
Okay. Here we go.
Now lift this off.
How long is this
gonna take, Mike?
About 40 minutes to get
the barbecue kiawe taste.
And I put it in a little pot,
and I --
Let it sit there
and steam itself?
Yeah, steam itself, right.
Grab this off the fire.
And take it off.
Nice and hot.
That's what
I'm talking about.
And we'll slice it all up.
We drizzle it
with a little sauce, here.
And we serve it
with a hot mustard sauce, yeah?
Sweet, smoky...
and it couldn't be better.
Roadside dining, baby,
at its finest,
in the middle of everything
you love about Hawaii.
You guys are making
killer food.
Your food hits the spot,
my friend.
Mike's the man.
You got to come see him.
FUSE: We've got char siu
with regular salad.
It's got the nice, crisp,
almost-burned edge to it,
which I just love the most.
The food is excellent,
and the ambience is, bar none,
the best place
on this side of the island.
And it's the perfect place
to hang with my family
and some of my closest friends.
Okay,
this is Logan and Brittany,
and everybody knows
Ryder, Lori,
Lisa, Dirty's girlfriend,
Dirty P.
So, we're all here
on vaca.
What do you guys think?
Dude,
I think it's phenomenal.
Anything you love more
than this?
There's one thing
I love more than this.
It's this lady, right here.
I love you even more
than anything in the world.
I really do.
Will you marry me?
Yes, honey. Aww.
You come here.
[ Laughter ]
Very nice.
That was awesome.
Cheers.
Don't expect it to end like this
all the time.
Don't worry. I'll be looking
for you next time on "Triple D."
It's all right here, right now,
on Paul and Lisa's wedding.
[ Laughter ]