Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Could you hurry up?
I need to get a seat.
...we're taking the Camaro
to the southernmost tip
of the U.S. of A.
That's right --
Key West, Florida.
This right here --
you get it all.
First stop...
You hear the music?
[ Hums "Rocky" theme ]
...the husband and wife team...
Look at that caramelization
on the sugar there.
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
...rockin' a food cart...
I might have melted
some wires there, son.
...with their own wild style.
You just got your own
history-making moment
in "Triple D."
Then we're hitting
a burrito joint...
I know fish taco.
That's good fish taco.
...turning up the serious
Mexican heat.
Aah! Whoa!
And on Duval Street...
Let's see this happen.
...a laid-back clam shack...
Which is exactly
what I like.
...dishing out
the perfect marriage
of Northeast flavor
and Southern style.
[ Rooster crows ]
What is up
with the roosters?
We're at the end
of civilization down here.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here
in Key West, Florida.
I mean,
you got to love this place,
even when the weather's
not the greatest.
Now I'm here in Old Town,
just a few blocks away
from Seaport.
Now, there are tons of great
restaurants around here,
so you know what I'm
looking for, right?
Exactly. A food truck.
Well, in this case, a food cart.
This is Garbo's Grill.
WOMAN: One order of fish tacos
coming right up.
Garbo's grill
is definitely number one.
It's amazing -- everything.
Burger, burger,
dub, burrito.
They have, you know, the five,
six things that they do,
and they do them
amazingly well.
The locals love it
because of Eli and Kenna.
FIERI:
Eli and Kenna Pancamo,
who showed up in town
as single tourists back in 2000.
Just when you moved here,
you met this character.
I did.
About six months in.
FIERI: And when they got
into the food biz,
they decided to keep it cozy
with a 40-square foot space
they picked up in 2011.
It was called Garbo's Grill
when you bought it?
KENNA: Correct.
Who is Garbo?
Her name was Heidi Garbo.
And they work very well
together.
It's a show. It's like
a sporting event, almost.
They cover a lot of ground
with their menu.
KENNA: Loaded umami burger,
bacon, cheese, tomato.
The Umami Burger's great.
It's by far
the best burger in town.
In the umami burger.
80/20 ground chuck,
a little bit of salt in here.
Ooh.
Whoa.
No humidity on there.
No humidity at all.
A little salt,
a little brown sugar,
pepper,
a little fresh garlic.
I like where it's going.
Fish sauce.
Ohh. Okay.
So, you're gonna use
the fat of this meat
with those ingredients
to create the flavor profile...
Yeah.
...and then the juiciness.
Get in there.
Get it all mixed up.
What music is playing
in your head right now?
[ Hums carnival music ]
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, that's a good one.
[ Both humming ]
8-ounce portions.
Great. Now to the flat top.
Yep.
Put the burger as a ball
on there
and let the grease from all
the fat circle around it.
After that's all done,
I'll just hand-patty it
with my hand down here.
I like to be one with it,
you know?
Just kind of have
that kind of bond.
So, I'm like, "Hey!
You're gonna be good.
You're gonna be
a good burger."
[ Laughs ]
I got myself
a little brioche bun here.
Just cook this side.
I'll flip it 'cause I'm gonna
put this tomato on top of it.
My bacon.
Gonna drop the cheese on it.
I use a chipotle gouda,
which is amazing.
I cover that thing up,
just melt it all around
where the cheese becomes
like the blanket
to keep that burger warm.
Keep that burger warm.
Yeah.
I can't say that I have had
many chipotle goudas.
It's really good-a.
It's...
[ Boing! ]
Did he just say that?
Yeah.
That's a "Triple D" first.
Oh, it's doing what I want.
Okay.
I'm ready to rock.
Are you?
Here we go.
You hear the music?
[ Hums "Theme from 'Rocky'" ]
See? Now he's got it.
The chipotle smoked gouda
is the bomb.
That needs to make it
into my repertoire.
It's hard to say
that you learn a new trick
in the world of burgers.
Letting the tomato get hot
and cook into that burger,
you have the ingredients there
of natural ketchup.
I'll tell you.
Really a righteous burger.
You just got your own
history-making moment
in "Triple D".
That's gangster, man.
Thank you very much.
I took one bite
and it just blew my mind.
MAN:
Definitely the top five.
Really?
Yes. It's awesome.
Awesome.
Did you already have one?
Are you allowed to buy two
when you come in line?
I tried. But that way I don't
have to wait in line again.
How long have you waiting
in line before?
About half an hour.
No matter how long the line is,
they're always saying hi to
people in the back of the line
and they're just making
everybody feel at home.
We've waited like 40 minutes
for a hot dog,
but we smiled the whole wait.
It's worth the wait
because the food's delicious.
FIERI: Even the food
has something to say about that.
It's just allowing the taco
to speak for itself.
Yeah, see?
What'd it say?
[ High-pitched ]
You like me.
When we come back...
Crazy.
[ Chuckles ]
Flat-out crazy.
FIERI: If you're looking
for Garbo's Grill
in Key West, Florida,
keep your eyes peeled
for a long line
and a funky two-wheeler.
Here, Eli and Kenna Pancamo
are serving it up with a smile
'cause these two
know how good they got it.
This is the greatest job
in the world.
Yes.
I mean,
you are in Key West.
You're hanging out
in a dirt parking lot.
You are a block
from the beach.
And you're making food
and people walk up
and you're the coolest dude.
Yeah, yeah.
Korean barbecue tacos
coming at ya.
MAN: The Korean barbecue taco
is a short rib taco.
It's delicious.
Honestly, I probably eat it
five times a week.
ELI: We're gonna do some
Korean barbecue, bulgogi.
Bulgogi?
Yeah.
You seem very Korean.
Let's get into it.
We got some
beef short rib.
We've already somewhat
trimmed it off the bone.
Nice thin slices.
Look at that. Beautiful.
We got this cut up.
Into the bowl right here.
Okay.
So, we're just gonna make our
little Korean barbecue marinade.
We're gonna start off
with some dark brown sugar,
fresh cut ginger,
fresh garlic, sesame oil.
Sesame oil.
A little
fish [High-pitched] sauce
It gets hot in here,
doesn't it?
[ Normal voice ] It does.
And a little [High-pitched] soy.
Might have melted some wires
there, son.
[ Normal voice ] Yeah,
I think I did.
And I put this lid on it,
and then we just hit it.
[ Boing! ]
Oh, oh.
What'd you forget?
Green onions?
Oh!
Yeah,
that would kind of help.
Yeah, that does help.
There we go.
Into the meat.
So, there we go.
Great.
Now, how long
do you let that marinate?
Just two and a half hours.
So, let's
make this stuff, huh?
You go in just --
right with your paw?
Right with my paw.
No measurements.
So, I'm gonna cover it.
'Cause
it will cook faster.
Keeps all that
moisture in.
I'll look at it.
[ High-pitched ]
Oh, look at that caramelization
on the sugar there.
Mmm, mmm, mmm,
mmm, mmm.
[ Normal voice ]
Flip that around.
I'm gonna cover it again.
I'm a happy guy.
You want to
get your tortilla ready.
What are we
gonna serve this with?
Dry slaw consists of
Napa cabbage,
daikon, carrots,
and scallions.
Put a little cilantro
in there.
I'm gonna put a little
citrus soy on that right now.
Okay.
My tongs out.
Then the Korean barbecue.
Yeah, getting a little bit
of caramelization.
Okay.
That's how she works.
Get a little sriracha.
You make
some good bulgogi.
The key to this really is
the phenomenal caramelization
and flavor of the meat.
That griddle is so hot,
it's just cooking on
that sauce -- not burning it.
'Cause there's a close line
to burning it.
Yeah.
But look at the juice
coming out of this.
Fresh made.
You got this
chewy, tender meat,
but then you get the nice
bright, fresh, crispiness
and you get that cilantro
coming through there.
It's just allowing the taco
to speak for itself, you know?
It's not a whole bunch
of special sauces or anything.
Yeah, see?
What'd it say?
[ High-pitched ]
You like me.
[ Cuckoo clock chimes ]
Crazy.
[ Chuckles ]
Flat-out crazy.
Hey, the bomb, dude.
Really.
It's sweet, it's spicy,
it's a good mix.
It's just amazing.
[ Chuckles ]
MAN: When you want something
really good,
Garbo's Grill is top-notch,
best place to go, bar none.
I've been to some funky joints
by some crazy people,
and you guys right now
are up there in the running.
But you folks
are doing it real deal.
And the great thing is,
you're doing it with a smile
and you're having
so much fun.
I mean, not just about the food.
It's about the experience.
Yep.
My brother, nice job.
FIERI: Coming up...
[ Sing-sing voice ]
That's gonna be hot!
...we're headed
to a funky burrito joint...
This right here,
that's a real burrito.
You're getting it all.
...rolling out
South-of-the-border street food.
This is getting more and more
Mexican as we go.
I told you.
[ Rooster crows ]
So, for my second stop
here in Key West,
I'm just down the street
from Garbo's Grill
to check out a joint
that's serving
exactly what
you'd expect to find -- Mexican.
And I'll tell you what.
It better be good.
This is Bad Boy Burrito.
Can I get
the Kobe beef burrito?
All the way?
All the way.
With a name
like Bad Boy Burrito,
you really want to be
putting out great burritos.
Got a veggie burrito.
I like a nice fat burrito,
plump, full of stuff.
FIERI: The chef and owner,
Chris Otten, and his wife, Erin,
have been rolling out
since 2007.
Could you hurry up?
I need to get a seat?
No. No.
No.
Sure,
they got the basics covered.
Beef burrito
and a naked steak burrito.
But they're definitely
not boxed in by the burrito.
Duck quesadillas
is one of my favorite dishes.
Flavor bursts in your mouth.
Fish tacos all set and ready.
WOMAN: Fish tacos are great.
A lot of times, the fish
is caught here locally,
same day.
What are we
gonna make first?
We're gonna make
the salsa verde
for the Cayo Hueso
fish tacos.
They Cayo Hueso
fish tacos?
Yes.
Hit it.
All right.
Garlic, jalapeños,
fresh lime juice.
And we're gonna
blend that up.
Then we're gonna
add cilantro.
Salt.
One little blitz.
And we're good to go.
It's a little spicy.
[ Smacks lips ]
Aah!
Like it?
[ Shouts indistinctly ]
Told you.
Mouth on fire.
Yeah. It's good for you.
Are we gonna
let this rest?
Are we gonna do anything
to this?
It's good to go.
That's just how we're gonna
administer that to the fish?
Exactly.
Now on to...?
We are gonna
cut up the fish.
Fresh seafood
down here in Key West
is like fresh corn
in Iowa.
Pretty much.
You butcher
all your own fish?
I do. Every day.
And what type of fish
is this?
This is a hogfish.
A hogfish.
Yes.
So, we take these.
How are we gonna season them?
We're gonna season them
with a little salt
and a mixture
of ground coriander,
cumin, and black pepper.
Dig it.
What are we cooking on?
Cooking on
a little flat top grill.
You actually
make the tortillas here?
Yes, by hand.
I'm impressed.
Yeah.
This is getting
more and more Mexican as we go.
I told you.
All right.
So, the fish on there.
Chopped onions.
The verde sauce
that we made.
Yes.
That fish
was caught today?
It was, speared.
Speared?
Speared, yes.
That's the only way
to catch the hogfish.
Nice.
Shaved cabbage on there.
Sour cream.
A little jalapeños.
Cilantro.
Some sliced radish.
And then a little pico de gallo
with your rice and beans.
Good stuff?
I know fish taco.
That's good fish taco.
Nice.
Real nice citrus notes.
Ohh, and that cilantro salsa
that you put on top...
The verde.
Ahh!
Coriander's a kicker.
Yeah.
And a little bit
of radish.
If you've ever had a street taco
in Mexico --
That radish.
You get the radish, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
I just wanted to verify it,
the whole...like that.
That's right.
I just want to make sure
you saw that.
[ Snaps fingers ]
WOMAN: Fish tacos, order up.
It's not something
you can get just anywhere,
so to have a hogfish taco is a
very rare and pleasurable thing.
Got fish tacos ready.
How would you describe
this type of restaurant,
this type of Mexican food
to people?
I just say
it's fresh and good.
When people come to town,
they want some place to go
that the locals go.
If you found this place,
you're most likely a local.
Definitely.
Absolutely.
Or you've watched
"Triple D."
WOMAN:
People think that Key West
is all about Duval Street,
you know?
Sure, it's great to Sloppy Joe's
and Hog's Breath
and check out all of those,
you know, tourist attractions,
but Key West
is really about the locals.
FIERI: And there's only about
25,000 that call it home.
MAN:
It's way off the beaten path.
I've been here
for about 11 years now.
I love life here.
It's simple.
FIERI:
A lot like the burritos here.
But Chris is always looking for
a way to go bigger and better.
Kobe beef burrito,
order up.
Made with dynamite
American-style Kobe beef.
The Kobe beef burrito --
excellent.
All right, brother.
What are you up to next?
We are gonna make
the mango habanero sauce
for the Kobe beef
burrito.
Charred mangos,
onions, and garlic.
Couple habaneros.
All right.
Now the liquid.
Help it smooth out a little bit.
Key West water.
Little salt.
[ Sing-song voice ]
That's gonna be hot!
[ Smacks lips ]
Wait for it.
Now it's coming through.
Yeah.
[ Strained ]
That's good.
Did you wait for it?
Yeah. Thanks a lot.
Let's make the burrito.
Little bit of oil.
In with the 80/20.
Nice fat.
Add some salt.
Coriander,
cumin, black pepper.
Cumin --
I was just gonna say,
there's your magic mix.
The house spice.
And then
a little chili powder.
We'll let this
cook down?
Yep.
What's first?
Black beans.
The basmati rice?
Basmati rice.
And now the beef.
A little sharp cheddar,
shaved cabbage...
Sour cream.
...sour cream,
some jalapeños,
picked cilantro,
a little pico de gallo,
and now
the mango habanero.
Oh, that's gonna be hot.
There we go.
And now a little
ancho chili relish.
And then roll it up.
You're getting a lot of flavors,
a lot of different textures,
hot, salty, sweet.
I mean,
you put the package together.
That's a good burrito.
Thanks.
I mean,
that's a really good burrito.
All right.
A little spicy,
a little...cabbagey.
Is cabbagey a word?
They got all kinds
of good things going on here.
It's a rarity in Key West
to find something
you can walk in, walk out,
10 bucks, and you have
an amazing meal.
I'm impressed.
You really are educating them
in real Mexican food.
I'm trying.
Love it.
Thanks.
FIERI: Up next...
Lobster roll.
...we're headed to the main drag
of Duval Street...
Rolling on
a littleneck.
...which has got a one-stop shop
for serious seafood.
The whole tag line is,
"Where Northern
and Southern seafood meet."
[ Rooster crows ]
So, to wrap up this "Triple D"
tour here at Key West, Florida,
I thought I'd bring you
to the belly of the beast.
The busiest street in the
entire town, this is Duval.
It runs from the Atlantic
to the Gulf,
and we're here
to check out a joint
that is doing some killer clams.
This is D.J.'s Clam Shack.
[ Rooster crows ]
If you're coming here
on a cruise,
D.J.'s Clam Shack
is the place to come.
Every time you come in,
you feel like a local.
FIERI: And if there's one thing
locals know,
it's fresh seafood...
Rolling on
a littleneck.
...served up by co-owners
Jeff Gagnon and Doug Bell,
who've been tapping into
their Northeastern
and Southern roots since '09.
Lobster roll.
Ipswich basket.
So, this is the fine mayor
of Key West.
What's the draw?
What do people
come to Key West for?
Our laid-back atmosphere,
our weather,
our architecture,
our culture.
And, if you're hungry...
Clams up!
...you come here for the clams.
Oh, the littleneck clams
are fantastic.
MAN: It's D.J.'s Clam Shack,
you know?
They didn't make the name
for no reason.
I see
the beautiful clams.
Yeah, we're gonna make up
some clams.
We're gonna do a little
garlic butter first.
It's gonna be one
of our ingredients.
We're starting with
some butter.
Some chopped garlic, basil,
and some oregano.
We're just gonna let that
slowly cook down.
That will be used
as the base
of what we're gonna
cook our steamers in.
That's is correct.
Gonna put our clams in.
We're gonna add
our white wine,
lemon juice,
a little celery in there.
Celery?
Yeah.
You know,
it eats the sauce.
The sauce gets absorbed in there
and it holds the flavor.
And now we're gonna add
the jalapeño.
Put a little lemon
in there.
We're gonna turn it up.
Soon as they open...
Soon as they open,
they'll be ready.
Whoa!
[ Rooster crows ]
Gonna come around.
What is up with the roosters?
Are they going 24/7?
[ Rooster crows ]
They're protected.
You can't mess with them.
We're at the end
of civilization down here.
Pour that
right on these bad boys.
We're gonna give you
a nice little chunk
of garlic bread on there
and add our lemon,
and send you on your way.
Where are
these clams from?
Those are actually
from the Great South Bay.
They're tender, juicy.
The broth is great.
It's not too overdone.
You know, sometimes the broth
can get too much.
You put jalapeño
in there.
[ Rooster crows ]
Is it in here?
The chicken?
The rooster.
Rooster. Yeah.
I don't have any problem
with the chicken.
The celery adds
a little sweetness to it.
The garlic bread
is out of bounds.
Pile it up like that.
I heard you guys
knew what you were doing.
That's real deal.
WOMAN:
Littleneck steamed clams.
You get the nice buttery taste,
but then the spice
of the jalapeño,
it's definitely
my favorite combination.
Where are you guys from?
Massachusetts.
Talk to me about the way
they're making it.
What do you think?
You can't beat it.
We're able to combine
both the seafood
from the North
and the South...
Fried shrimp up!
...which is exactly
what I like.
They really put a lot of pride
into their work here
and it shows.
We happen to be down here
in Key West, Florida,
and run into
one of my great buddies
and also
my tattoo artists,
the guy who does
all my illustrations
for all my cookbooks.
This is the infamous
Joe Leonard.
Good stuff?
They're amazing.
Nice job. You guys have really
pulled it off, man.
Killer.
Thank you very much, man.
Thanks.
If you stick around, we can
get you some fresh chicken.
[ Rooster crows ]
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives".
[ Horn honks ]
Yo, Guy.
Yo, yo! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!