Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That is outstanding.
...we're getting
big-time bites...
I don't know
how to break this down.
...of some serious flavor.
That's right,
Alice!
On the outskirts
of Queens, New York...
Oh, my gosh!
...the "where are we?" joint...
Never seen anything
like this.
...serving up
real-deal Vietnamese.
I could eat this thing
till my head falls off.
In Manhattan's East Village...
Activate the proteins.
...one chef channels another...
Is that you?
Yes.
...for an out-of-bounds take
on a classic.
It really is
a dynamite burger.
And in Eureka, California,
the down-home spot...
I don't know whether
to attack it with a chain saw,
a canoe paddle.
...where the oven
is always the answer.
You're gonna make
a mess.
Is that
what we're gonna with?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, just going to.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here in Ridgewood, Queens.
Now, I'm about, let me think,
about a thousand miles away
from downtown Manhattan.
Actually, I'm only 5 miles away,
but it seems like
I'm way out here.
I mean,
I'm in this industrial park.
We've got
a scrap-metal joint there,
we've got a concrete plant
over here.
You're saying,
"Guy, why are you so far out?"
Listen, I hear they got a joint
with the bomb Vietnamese food.
This is Bun-Ker.
Shrimp going out.
It's in the middle of nowhere.
[ Laughs ]
MAN: And the food --
it just hits my heart, you know?
I love it.
Here's your traditional
banh xeo.
It's like you're eating
in Vietnam.
FIERI:
Central Vietnam, to be exact,
where Chef Jimmy Tu's mom
and dad were raised.
Cha ca going out.
In 2013, he took
what his mama taught him
and tricked out a menu loaded
with Vietnamese street food.
We got about five minutes
on these pork chops.
The grilled pork chops here
are absolutely incredible.
It is my favorite.
All right, so,
what are we gonna make?
A marinade
for the suon nuong xa.
Suon nuong xa?
Yeah.
Lemongrass grilled pork.
Okay.
We got garlic,
Thai chili peppers.
Okay.
Lemongrass,
shallots.
And this is all
just for the marinade?
Yeah.
And we're gonna put it
in here
and hit it
with the mortar and pestle?
Yeah.
So,
breaking this down.
Yeah.
So, this is really
opening it up,
bringing all
that flavor out.
Now we're gonna put it
in a bowl.
And to this,
we're gonna add sea salt.
Sugar?
Sugar.
Fish sauce, canola oil,
and this is Chinese XO sauce.
It's like
a Chinese barbecue sauce.
Stir that up.
You could marinate
a seat cushion in it
and that'd
taste great.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm.
So, we'll cut
the pork loin.
This is
a Berkshire pork loin.
We have to use
good ingredients.
Gorgeous!
Yeah.
All right, so,
right in here to the marinade?
Mix it
in there.
Seven to eight hours?
Yep.
Killer.
The marinated pork chops
go on the grill
for about five minutes.
Now, you can see all the fibers
of that lemongrass
sticking to the pork.
Plate this.
Pork chop
right here.
Scallion oil.
Crispy pork skin.
And egg,
right?
Don't pop that yolk.
Out of bounds!
This is tender,
super flavorful.
Mmm!
Juicy, rich.
You get in
some of these pickled veg.
A little garlic.
That really is,
without question,
one of the best pork chops
I've ever had.
Mmm!
I could eat this thing
till my head falls off.
MAN:
Here's your suon nuong xa.
A little bit crunchy
on the outside,
tender on the inside,
and seasoned perfectly.
Mmm.
The runny egg over the top
slices through it like butter.
Oh, my God.
It's just delicious.
Mmm.
Beef going out.
It's a type of food
that you come here, and you eat,
and you're thinking about it
all week.
FIERI:
It's that kind of obsession
that makes this place
a pilgrimage worth making.
I like it for the quaint view
of the scrap metal.
What was here
before you?
When we started here,
we were doing
boutique seafood distribution.
Okay.
Hence the weird location.
But then Sandy hit us,
we got flooded.
Here?
Yeah.
It was a mess.
Really?
Yeah.
So, you came in,
you built this out?
I always wanted
to do Vietnamese street food.
So, while the flooded building
became the inspiration for the
name, the menu is pure comfort.
We're talking
lemongrass short ribs,
caramelized shrimp, or this dish
that comes
with a fanatical following.
The crispy crepe
changed my life.
What's the first thing
we're gonna make?
Our banh xeo batter.
Fire it up.
We got rice flour, turmeric,
sea salt, water.
It's very simple.
Once that's nicely mixed,
add our scallions.
That's it?
That's it.
Get this pan hot,
add a little oil.
This is Heritage bacon
that's smoked,
combined
with the shrimp.
I like
that you're cooking hot.
Yeah.
Now we add the batter.
Nuts!
That rice flour falls underneath
the oil and the bacon fat,
and it's just soaking it up
at the same time.
Whoa!
Easy on the egg.
Trying to cut down on it.
There you go.
That's plenty.
We add
some bean sprouts.
This looks good.
We fold it over.
Never seen anything
like this.
Trim this off.
And this is how it gets served,
on the bamboo board?
Yeah.
Okay, so, I load it up
like this?
Yeah.
Grab whatever herbs you want.
Basil,
a little mint.
Yeah.
Wrap it up.
Dip it like this?
Yep.
Mmm.
That is nuts!
[ Chuckles ]
See --
Oh, my gosh!
I don't know
how to break this down
about what
is more fantastic.
This right here with the bacon
and the scallions
and the crispiness
and the shrimp.
That is wicked good,
dude.
Mmm!
Banh xeo going out.
It's crispy, but it's also soft.
It's all melty.
The freshness
of the bean sprouts,
the savoriness
of the bacon and the shrimp.
Bun-Ker food has probably
the best aspects
of every Southeast Asian
cooking cuisine out there.
I think
if it's the last meal on earth,
I'm gonna have it right here.
Mmm.
I've eaten great food, but this,
without question, is dynamite.
Excellent job.
Thank you, man.
FIERI: Up next...
Oh, yeah.
Practically a whole duck
and half of Idaho.
We're headed over
to Manhattan's East Village
to put a buddy's claim...
This burger is, in my opinion,
the best hamburger in America.
...to the test.
80/20?
70/30.
70/30?
My kind of burger.
I'm here in New York City
in the East Village
to check out a joint that I hear
has this eclectic
scratch-made menu,
but better yet, it comes
really highly recommended
from a buddy of mine
who is, like,
a big-shot burger aficionado.
This is the Brindle Room.
Baked oysters.
Just melts in your mouth.
Duck Confit Poutine.
MAN: It's a hidden gem.
One of the better meals
you'll have in this area.
Mexican Moules Frites.
FIERI:
And Chef Jeremy Spector's menu
is keeping
the interest level high.
From Pumpkin Gratin
and beer-battered pork belly,
to -- get this --
potato doughnuts.
That's totally Jeremy
to do something crazy.
WOMAN: He's worked
at some of the best restaurants
in the city.
And he wanted to give up
all the cool flash
and do a neighborhood joint
where you can come
and eat stuff you like
but push it a little bit
into the edge.
FIERI: But he's knocking it
out of the park
with a familiar classic, too.
Brindle Room burger,
medium, with American.
It is the best burger
I've ever eaten.
So, the buddy
I told you about
really is
a big-shot burger aficionado,
and that's this guy,
Josh Ozersky.
This burger,
the Brindle Room,
is in my opinion --
my professional opinion --
the best hamburger
in America.
FIERI: And it all starts
with a high-end grind.
This is
for burger?!
This and this outer cap
is for burger.
So, you got a big bone-in
prime rib here,
pull off
all that beautiful fat,
mix it here
with this big piece of chuck?
Yes.
A little bit of extra fat,
and that's it.
Nothing weird.
80/20?
70/30.
70/30?
It's a lot of fat.
My kind of burger.
So, I'm gonna mix this up
with my hand.
I'm just gonna activate
the proteins just a little bit.
Activate the proteins.
Everybody makes
their burgers differently.
Some people
don't pack them at all.
pack them lightly.
We pack them
a little bit medium.
Okay.
I have
this pipe here.
Put that on top.
And we
form our burger.
It's only
about 6 ounces.
Okay.
And there's our patty
right there.
[ Whistles ]
How are we
gonna cook this?
Salt, pepper, just a drop
of oil, cast-iron skillet.
Fire it up,
dude.
Super hot, both sides.
We have
American cheese.
We add a little bit
of caramelized onions on there.
Toasted bun.
And the two pickles?
Just to garnish.
And that's
all she wrote?
That's it.
No tomato,
no...?
No tomato, no lettuce,
just a very pedestrian bun.
It's only 6 ounces,
but it's very meaty, very rich.
The bun
works out fantastic.
Caramelized onions are nice,
a little sweetness to it.
Crust that you built
in that screaming,
smoking-hot
cast-iron skillet.
I like the juiciness of it,
the cheese melting into it.
Mmm.
It really is
a dynamite burger.
The first time I bit in
that burger, I was amazed.
It tastes unlike
any other burger in New York.
I think it's really juicy
and really excellent.
He's been cooking
since he's 7 years old.
His food
has always been delicious.
FIERI:
And while he's picked up skills
cooking everywhere
from Cali to London
to Food Network's "Chopped,"
he's also drawing
a little inspiration
from a late-'70s sitcom.
So, talk to me
about Mel's Diner, baby.
That's our buddy Mel Sharples,
the old-school cook
on the TV show "Alice."
Mean.
Opinionated.
Yeah.
Kind-hearted, though.
Yes.
Loved people.
Is that you?
Yes.
And when we come back...
Here's your
Duck Confit Poutine.
...he's gonna show us
just how much.
What are you doing
serving duck poutine?
I'll serve whatever I want
and when I want.
That's right,
Alice!
FIERI: At the Brindle Room in
the East Village of Manhattan,
Chef Jeremy Spector
has created a menu
of rocking American favorites...
Killer burger.
Killer burger?
...to go with some
international comfort classics.
Here's your
Duck Confit Poutine.
FIERI: A high-end version
of the Canadian favorite.
It's delectable and savory.
It's, like,
the perfect combination of food.
FIERI:
Are you from Canada?
No.
From France?
Not quite.
What are you doing
serving duck poutine?
I'll serve whatever I want
and when I want.
That's right,
Alice!
Yeah.
So,
what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make our jus
for our Duck Confit Poutine.
Okay.
Let's get after this.
First, I'm gonna add my roasted
chicken bones, roasted carrots.
Mirepoix.
Got onions, celery.
Now I'm gonna add
my brown chicken stock.
So, we're gonna cook
this down?
Yes.
We're gonna strain it, and then
we're gonna further reduce it,
so we get a really thick,
flavorful gravy.
Dig it.
Okay.
Break it down.
All right.
I got my Long Island duck
right here.
And are we saving
this skin?
So, the skin we're gonna
render down for the duck confit.
Okay.
And we take out
the leg.
Okay.
So, I have my duck carcass.
We're gonna use
to make this a stock.
Got it.
Get that out of the way.
Legs for confit right here.
Great.
And I have a few more
already done.
Next, I'm going to add cinnamon,
bay leaf, whole garlic,
a little bit of orange rind,
whole black peppercorns.
Shallots?
Shallots.
Thyme, sage,
and rosemary and salt.
This is gonna sit
overnight.
So, we're gonna do
kind of a dry brine?
Exactly.
Bring it out,
hit it with the duck fat,
fill it up,
go to the oven.
And when we roast it in the oven
with the duck fat...?
250 for three hours.
Okay.
So,
this is our finished confit.
Cooled down,
yes?
Cooled down.
We're gonna pull the confit,
save the fat.
And when I fry
my French fries...
Yes?
...that's gonna go
in there.
You drop a little in there.
Gotcha.
I'm gonna pull
the meat.
Look at that.
It's nice and tender.
Gorgeous.
Oh,
that's tasty.
A little of that orange peel
coming through,
a little cinnamon.
Outrageous, my friend.
Okay,
next step.
So, we got our duck
in a pan.
We're gonna put
our jus in.
I'm gonna let that
heat up.
I'm gonna bring it to a boil,
and I'm gonna add the slurry.
Then we'll go
to the slurry. Got it.
All right, so,
we have our hand-cut fries.
Nice.
We got our duck skin
in here.
We are going to toss in
our cheese curds.
A little tossing.
The trick
is that you layer everything
so each bit
has cheese curds,
has French fries,
and it has duck and sauce.
So, we're gonna put
a little bit down,
top it off with another layer of
French fries and cheese curds.
Duck skin.
Nice.
And finally, one more layer
of sauce and duck.
Finish with parsley.
And that's all she wrote.
That's it.
Well, we have practically
a whole duck and half of Idaho.
[ Scoffs ]
This is
out of bounds.
I got to tell you,
this is ridiculous.
The way
you confit your duck...
...with the peel
and garlic and the shallots,
and putting
all this together
with the hand-cut fries
and the cheese curds --
and look at the creaminess
of this.
It's outrageous.
Every aspect of that dish works.
It's salty, it's cheesy, it's
gooey, crunchy with the fries.
All my favorite things
on one plate.
I love this place.
Excellent job.
FIERI:
Coming up...
This is
mushroom mayhem!
We're headed
to Eureka, California...
[ Whistles ]
...where a brick-oven spot...
And into
the magic oven.
...is turning up
some serious heat.
That is outstanding.
So, I've been wanting to shoot
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
up here in Northern California
for a long time.
And when I say
Northern California,
I'm talking about my hometown
area of Humboldt County.
Now, a few years ago,
I was at this joint
enjoying their wood-fired oven
and their use
of local ingredients.
I knew one day I'd be back.
This is Brick & Fire.
Oysters are ready.
And the food
is always amazingly fresh.
WOMAN: A lot has to do with Jim.
Brick Bird for ya.
Jimmy is probably the best chef
in Humboldt County.
He has a little garden
across the street,
and I know that that's
gonna wind up on my plate.
And I'm very happy.
FIERI: That's music to the ears
of owner and chef Jim Hughes
because it's the bounty
of Humboldt County
that sealed the deal
back in 2010.
Walked in the door,
and instantly,
I knew that this was the spot
I'd been looking for for years.
Seriously?
Yeah.
And we opened
four weeks after that.
He's churning out everything
from fresh seafood...
Order up, cedar-planked salmon.
FIERI:
...to unique veggie dishes
like the grilled romaine Caesar.
When they first opened,
I would obsess about it.
FIERI:
But it's this best seller
that sums up Jimmy's commitment
to local...
The Mushroom Cobbler.
FIERI: ...stuffed with at least
a half-dozen wild mushrooms.
MAN:
It's very tasty,
and I can probably eat two
or three of them.
What are
we on to now?
Now we're gonna do
the Wild Mushroom Cobbler.
So, first,
what we're gonna do
is start off soaking
some dried wild mushrooms --
porcinis, chanterelles,
morels in there,
and some
dried shiitakes.
Just gonna cover that
with enough water.
So,
dried mushrooms first.
So, let these steep
and rehydrate.
And how long?
About 15,
20 minutes.
While that's working,
what's up?
Start the base
of the cobbler here.
Olive oil, chopped shallots,
and onions.
Okay, so, sweat down
the shallots and the onions?
Exactly.
Now I'm gonna add
some cold butter
and the mushrooms that
we roasted in the brick oven.
Fresh oyster,
creminis.
Got the mushrooms in there now
stewing in the butter.
And we can add in
some sherry vinegar.
Now we come in
with the dehydrated mushrooms
that we reconstituted?
Yep.
Chopped them up fine.
This is
mushroom mayhem.
And then,
just for some more mushroom,
we take
dried porcini mushrooms
and put them
in the coffee grinder.
There we go.
Powder.
'Cause if we don't have
enough mushroom flavor,
we're gonna inject it.
That's right.
And a little
fresh thyme.
Let that
reduce down.
Water.
The steeping juice
from before.
Sure.
Adds a little flavor.
A little heavy cream.
And a little S&P.
A little salt and pepper.
Excellent.
FIERI:
Then it all comes together
with the help
of Jimmy's enormous wood oven.
How hot
is this thing?
Well,
it starts at about 700...
Thousand degrees.
Now we're gonna make
the biscuit.
All-purpose flour.
Salt, sugar,
baking powder.
Okay.
Get a little mix.
Milk, melted butter,
and cheese.
And that's
all she wrote?
That's it.
Okay.
Just lay 'em out?
Yeah.
Now our biscuits
will go in the oven
about 400 degrees
for about 20 minutes.
So, we take our cobbler mix
that we made.
Just fill up a ramekin
with the nice, hot mushrooms.
Biscuit.
A little Parm.
And into the magic oven.
Yep.
Just to where
the cheese will melt?
Yeah, it'll get
a little brown color.
All right.
[ Whistles ]
A little Humboldt green
to hold it in place.
A little parsley.
I don't know whether
to attack it with a chain saw,
a canoe paddle.
You're gonna make
a mess.
Is that
what we're gonna go with?
Yeah. Yeah.
You're just going to.
That is outstanding!
The depth of the oyster
and the chanterelle
and the portobello
and the cremini --
It just goes on
and on.
Cooking down the shallots,
the caramelized onions,
get that sweetness
coming through.
Then, texturally,
the biscuit.
Anybody says they're not a
mushroom fan, that would be...
Mushroom Cobbler.
It's super rich, super decadent.
It's delicious.
If you were blindfolded
and you had to do a taste test,
you could tell
it's coming from the brick oven.
Chef,
awesome job.
Turn off the cameras,
close the doors,
get some wine,
make some more.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Look at this.
Look at the beautiful,
caramelized,
Maillard-flavored crust
that goes from edge to edge.
Then --
Hey,
time out.
Did he just use "Maillard"
on "Triple D"?
[ Laughs ]
All right.
Back to you, Mr. Maillard.