Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Epic.
...we're pairing up
with some dynamite duos.
Sounds good.
In Manhattan's East Village...
Ohh! Smell this.
...the brother-and-sister
team...
Looks kind of like
a hip-hop boy band.
...showing off their wings...
These are gonna be outrageous.
I can already tell.
...and exposing their necks.
Top three best goat dishes
I've ever had.
In Miami, Florida...
So you're an inventor.
...a sibling operation
with a tasty sense of tradition.
My parents are great cooks,
and my grandparents
were even better cooks.
And in Eureka, California...
Is this really
how big this thing is?
...one couple gives it all up...
So, you guys have taken
a gigantic leap of faith.
...to tap in to their own
particular passions.
Creole-Mediterranean fusion.
Yeah.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So I'm here in New York City
in the East Village.
Now, this is pretty familiar
territory for "Triple D."
Let's see, we got The Redhead,
we got the Brindle Room,
and, of course, John's on 12th
right down the street here.
Now, we're here
to check out a joint
where a brother and sister have
partnered up with some buddies,
and they got this restaurant
with a pretty eclectic menu.
This is Ducks Eatery.
Everything is just
pretty much untouchable.
Crispy pig-ear
lettuce wraps.
Definitely
flies under the radar.
FIERI: Not for long.
Word about this joint
has ripped through the city
since it started in 2012 by
siblings Will and Julie Horowitz
and a few friends.
Looks kind of like
a hip-hop boy band
with the lead singer
right here, you know?
All right,
I'm about to simmer these.
You can tell that they have
a real passion for it.
Where did you learn to cook?
My grandparents on both sides
were chefs.
I learned out in Colorado,
Southeast Asia.
A lot of influence
from traveling.
JULIE: We have
the jerk chicken wings here.
They're always
trying new things.
Goat neck up. Table 5.
I'm having the goat's neck,
and it is delicious.
So, why goat neck?
I was in Nepal, and in Nepal,
they have this famous dish
that's, like, goat-feet
or lamb-feet curry.
We loved the flavors.
We wanted, like,
a big chunk of meat.
It turned out that the neck
was perfect for smoking.
So let's get into this.
Fresh garlic.
Palm sugar.
Ground dried Thai chilies.
Here's some star anise,
coriander, some dried bay.
We have
some black cardamom.
We're gonna add
a little green cardamom, too.
Are we gonna get after
the entire spice cabinet?
Big part of what we do.
Some regular black peppercorn.
We get it
from southern Vietnam.
Juniper berries.
Kaffir leaf.
Ohh! Smell this.
You guys didn't pay your
subscription for Smell-O-Vision.
Then we start adding all of
our dried powder ingredients.
More is getting added
to this?
So much more.
This is just half.
It needs togarashi chili.
Love togarashi.
My favorite.
Regular old dried cayenne.
Some garlic powder.
Some onion powder.
Some mustard seed.
We have paprika.
Yellow turmeric.
We have some chili powder,
brown sugar,
and a little bit of salt
in here.
We're gonna start adding in
some of our liquids.
Vietnamese fish sauce.
Dark Thai soy sauce.
And then we're gonna emulsify a
little bit of water inside here.
It's great, right?
Mmm!
Get in there.
Have a taste.
Get out!
Now we're gonna take
our goat necks,
and we're gonna place them
in our marinade.
Necks into the fridge --
24 hours.
Let's get after this.
We're smoking with
what kind of wood?
WILL: Mostly oak
and a little bit of hickory.
About seven hours,
about 225.
Let's take these guys
out of the smoker.
Whoo!
These are gonna be
outrageous.
I can already tell.
Put it back in the marinade,
braise it this way.
All right, in the oven
four and a half, five hours.
Whoa!
WILL: Exactly.
Dude!
We got our cast iron going.
Okay.
Gonna start off by just throwing
a little bit of butter in there.
This is our master fat --
bacon fat
and pickled pastrami fat.
That's the fat?
This just can't get
any more ridiculous.
Just baste it with fat.
Spread your glaze
a little bit.
Baste a little bit more.
Dried sour cherries.
Nice call.
It's got to reduce all the way
with some of our au jus.
It just reduced,
so it's just gelatinized.
All right, cool. Are we ready
to plate this thing?
Let's go.
Rice.
The most careful part.
FIERI:
That's ridiculous.
Look at this, dude.
What a dish.
Yeah, give that a try.
We're gonna finish this
with a little bit of cilantro
on top, too.
Ohh,
it's ridiculously good.
Tender, juicy meat.
Rich, well-rounded.
Oh, and when you get
one of those cherries...
That's got to be in
the top three best goat dishes
I've ever had.
Amazing.
This guy's out-of-bounds!
The meat is literally
melting off of the bone.
It's incredibly flavorful.
Oh, my gosh.
It's delicious.
Intense but subtle.
I could stick my head in it.
[ Laughs ]
This is the famous Nicky
Sitnycky from John's on 12th.
Unfortunately,
we lost your partner.
Mikey 2 Names.
Yeah, Mikey 2 Names.
You guys were business partners
for how many years?
Almost 41 years.
Great guy and very missed.
I had a blast making meatballs
with him,
cooking with him
in the kitchen.
These meatballs
are giving me trouble.
What's the story, Guy?
All right.
He's talking
to the meatballs.
What do you think
of this place?
Luscious, scrumptious.
This is all family here,
just like John's.
FIERI: Which means
we're gonna stay a while.
When we come back...
WILL:
Julie, wings. Table 2.
...we're tucking in to
the Ducks' take on wings.
What you come up with is big,
flavorful, unique styles.
FIERI: "Triple D" is parked
at Ducks Eatery
on one of NYC's best streets
for eats -- East 12th.
Here, Will Horowitz
and his sister, Julie,
are putting
deep, worldly flavors
into a backpacker's dream menu.
Even the chicken wing
is definitely a thing.
WILL:
Julie, wings. Table 2.
Had some jumbo chicken wings...
Which were insane.
I've made a complete mess
of myself
just shoveling wings
in my mouth.
We're gonna do some
whole, smoked chicken wings.
Start off
by just making our marinade.
We have some palm sugar,
brown sugar,
a little bit of white,
northern Indian yellow curry,
black pepper, a little bit more
of that green cardamom,
some fresh garlic,
chopped shallots,
lemongrass, Kaffir lime leaves,
a whole load of cilantro stems.
I lost count at 40.
[ Laughs ]
Dark soy sauce,
apple-cider vinegar,
fish sauce from Vietnam,
a whole bunch of limes.
This has a real strong lime sort
of flavor to the whole thing.
We're gonna get in there,
try and mix it all around,
let those flavors marry
a little bit.
Whole chicken wings.
Yep.
We're gonna dump it
right over here.
Just gonna pour on
some water.
Let that sit and brine
overnight.
We'll air-dry them
for a little bit,
then we're gonna
smoke them.
About 210, 225.
These guys have been in here
for about four hours now.
Let them cool down,
dry a little bit,
then we'll hit them
to the fryer.
Chill out for a bit.
This is our jerk sauce.
Let it marry a little bit.
Crazy.
That's it. Simple.
Mmm!
I like when it's a big wing,
'cause you get the opportunity
to leave all the juices inside.
So you get all that flavor
left in there.
The way you guys
play this smoker
is complementing the brine
and the sauce so well.
What you come up with
is just really flavorful,
big, unique style.
Awesome job, brother.
Really.
What do you think
of these wings?
Theres fruitiness, there's
sweetness, there's peppery.
I love it.
The guy that shot
my promo package
when I got on
"The Next Food Network Star"
and helped start me and my whole
career -- Neil Regan.
Huge mistake.
[ Both laugh ]
It's just something that you
really can't find anywhere else.
Awesome place, man.
Great creativity,
using old-school fundamentals,
techniques, and methods.
Bringing out big flavor.
Killer.
Thanks, brother.
Awesome job.
FIERI: Coming up...
"You did what?"
...we're headed
to Miami, Florida...
That is tender, porky,
fall-apart-y.
...for some authentic
southern surf and turf.
This is the best
of both worlds.
So I'm here in South Miami.
Well, actually,
almost Coral Gables.
What do you get here?
Awesome homes,
really cool shops,
and killer restaurants,
like this joint -- Whisk.
Everything in here is just
so fresh and so delicious.
BRENDAN:
Cornmeal-fried okra.
It's the southern, gourmet,
low-country restaurant.
Shrimp and grits for you,
sir.
And there's nothing like it
in Miami.
Fried-green-tomato salad.
Right on time.
FIERI:
And the man with the plan is
Miami's own Chef Brendan Connor,
whose academic pursuits led him
to the Carolina low country
for reasons other than food.
I heard there was
a 7-1 girl-to-guy ratio
at the College of Charleston.
And while he did earn a degree
in history,
he also got a killer education
in some of Charleston's
best joints.
And in 2011, he and his sister,
Kristin, opened up this spot,
serving up the low-country meals
they grew up on.
My parents are great cooks,
and my grandparents
were even better cooks.
And we took a lot
of what their basics were
and refined them
a little bit.
And he's even putting a twist on
fresh seafood from the coast...
Whole-fried snapper.
...by topping it with a
scratch-made Asian peanut sauce.
Kind of like a Caribbean
meets southern home cooking
kind of dish.
It's quite flavorful.
We're gonna start scoring
and preparing this fish here.
We can use yellowtail.
We can use red snapper.
Lane snapper's what they had
for us today.
First thing we do to prepare it
is cut off the fins --
side and the bottom.
Next we are going to
diamond-score
so that it makes it easier
for you to eat.
FIERI: It also gets --
If we're gonna fry this,
it's nice
to be able to get in there
with some of
the crunch-a-taciousness.
That's an Uncle Bo
right there.
Crunch-a-taciousness,
indeed.
Yep.
Okay.
We want to make sure
it can talk to you
when it goes out
onto the plate.
Naturally, a little bit
of salt and pepper.
Dredge it lightly
in corn starch.
Oh, nice and crunchy.
That's right.
Now we'll go to the fryer?
To the fryer we go.
Are we frying
in anything special?
Peanut oil? 10-40?
Peanut oil.
Of course you do.
You're a low-country kitchen.
You got to be running
peanut oil.
Always peanut oil.
So we've got
our whole-fried fish
ready to go,
ready to hit the plate.
Got to take the skewer
out of the mouth.
Epic.
And ready for a little bit of
that low-country peanut sauce.
Look at that.
I like to finish it off
with some fresh cilantro
right there
in the pocket.
Oh.
Look at that.
That is awesome.
If you like fried fish
but you like real fish flavor,
whereas a lot of times,
fried fish will kind of get lost
using fish that doesn't have
a lot of flavor,
this is the best
of both worlds.
The crunchy texture
of the fried fish,
all the flavor coming from
the bones and the skin,
really,
it is the best of both worlds.
Outrageous, man.
Killer dish.
Thank you.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
Snapper.
FIERI: Is it? Hands down?
Hands down.
Cooked to perfection.
This is our second home.
I feel like I'm family
whenever I come in the door.
FIERI: 'Cause comfort food's
always been important
for the Connor family.
Every time we'd go eat
with our grandparents,
there were biscuits and gravy
freshly made every morning,
fried chicken
that'll knock your socks off.
So he's re-creating
that same feeling,
even if it means
doing things a little different.
We wanted to do ribs here.
We don't have a smoker,
so we decided we'd braise them.
So this is what
we came up with --
beer-braised
baby-back ribs.
We started with this rub here --
powdered garlic, onion --
granulated --
oregano, chili powder,
salt and pepper,
and brown sugar.
Being from the south
and the low-country cooking,
I mean,
what does your grandpa say
about you not having a smoker
for these ribs?
[ Southern accent ]
"You did what?"
He might be
a little disappointed,
but I think the final product
he'd be all right with.
We get in
a nice, meaty rib.
That's a big baby back.
That's a big baby-back rib.
Now it's time
to rub the ribs.
Make sure to apply this
very liberally.
Now you're gonna
let them marinate?
Overnight.
When they're done
marinating,
we'll put them on a hot char
grill with some salt and pepper
to really caramelize
the brown sugar on the meat.
Now that we've
charred the ribs,
we're gonna add some mirepoix
to it,
our beer, our veg stock...
...wrap it in plastic,
then foil,
and then we're ready
to go to the oven.
What temp?
300 degrees.
For how long?
About two hours.
There you go.
Steamy reveal for you, sir.
Nice.
That dark beer right on top
of that -- out-of-bounds.
Good. All right,
we'll hit the grill.
Take some of
our molasses barbecue sauce,
flipping it over.
Green onion.
Now it's ready.
Look at that.
That is tender, porky,
fall-apart-y.
I got to be honest.
I'm not a fan of braised ribs,
typically.
This, however, with the dry rub
that goes for the 24 hours --
really
penetrating that flavor.
With the mirepoix,
that dark beer,
and hit with this
molasses barbecue sauce...
I got to be honest, man, you
have really done a great job.
Thank you.
Very tender.
Falls off the bone.
It has, like,
nothing wrong with it.
It's just perfect.
He really pays attention to the
food and makes it very special.
I have never been disappointed
with anything I've ordered here.
This has
the low-country attitude
with the sophisticated approach
to the presentation.
Thanks, man.
Congratulations.
FIERI: Up next...
Are you there?
Yeah, someplace in here.
...we're headed
to Eureka, California,
for a mom-and-pop shop...
That's some of the best
out-of-the-oven pulled pork
I've had.
...serving up
the savory pulled-pork sandwich.
♪ Pulled pork, pulled pork ♪
Did you just make a little song
about that?
I did.
So I'm here
in Eureka, California.
Now, that's like 20 miles north
of my home town of Ferndale.
I'm here to check out a joint
where this husband-and-wife team
quit
their big-shot corporate jobs
to get into
the restaurant business.
Crazy.
This is Café Nooner.
Pasta plate.
They always have
an interesting mix of flavors.
The food is to die for.
Everything I've ever eaten
off the menu is amazing.
Lamb plate.
FIERI:
Love of food was the one thing
Lorrena Filgas and her husband,
Joe, did have.
A lot of experience?
Not so much.
So you guys have taken
a gigantic leap of faith
buying this.
You haven't been
in the restaurant business.
No.
Temperature on that is medium,
correct?
Yes, sir.
All right.
What kind of food
do you do here?
We do
a Creole-Mediterranean fusion.
Creole-Mediterranean fusion?
Yeah.
Climates are the same
in Greece and Louisiana.
Oh, yeah, that's how
I was looking at it.
What makes their food here
so delicious?
They do a lot
of local ingredients
and a lot
of organic ingredients.
FIERI:
That's an understatement.
Lorrena keeps it real
by supporting over 17 different
Humboldt County producers.
Always, year-round, they find
a way to have fresh food,
and it's fantastic.
Pulled pork
with apple slaw.
WOMAN: Thank you.
You're welcome.
♪ Pulled pork, pulled pork ♪
Did you just make a little song
about that?
I did.
We are making Creole spice,
and we use this
to rub our pulled pork.
We use it in a couple
of our other recipes.
It's really awesome stuff.
Okay, fire it up.
Okay. It gets paprika.
Granulated onion.
Granulated garlic.
You're right on it.
Cumin.
Thyme.
A little thyme.
A little old bay.
Allspice.
White pepper.
Black pepper.
Sea salt.
I see it.
And a little cayenne.
Doctor.
Thank you, sir.
So you'll use this
interchangeably
on a variety of the different
proteins you work with.
Whoa!
Yeah.
Okay. Pork butt.
Basically, we're just gonna get
this spice mix
everywhere we can get it.
Flip it over
because this is what's gonna
make it taste good.
And then we'll do
some Worcestershire.
Worcestershire-shire-shire.
A little liquid smoke.
And last, but not least...
A little Humboldt hot sauce,
and this is an habanero-mango.
Wrap it in foil.
What temp are we going at?
350 for five hours.
For five hours.
There you go.
Uh-oh.
[ Laughs ]
Are you there?
Yeah, someplace in here.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, and then we're just gonna
pull this the old-fashioned way.
Right in that juice.
Now we're gonna go
to the flat top
to get a little crust on it.
Mm-hmm.
Put a little bit of our barbecue
right on that.
Then we're gonna put a little
barbecue sauce on this side.
And this guy has got his
brown caramelization on there.
And then we dress it.
Is this really
how big this thing is?
Yeah.
Gets a little pickle
and a pepper on it.
Look at that.
That is ridiculous.
The liquid smoke, the dry rub,
the Worcestershire,
the Humboldt
habanero hot sauce...
...all of that together --
That's some of the best
out-of-the-oven pulled pork
I've had.
You killed this. Ohh!
Thank you.
I don't know how they
make it crispy and tender
at the same time. Love it.
WOMAN:
The barbecue sauce is --
I honestly would like
to take a bath in it.
FIERI: This was my English
teacher in my sophomore
year of high school.
This is Mr. Pulitono.
A man
with a mustache my size --
I need a stack of napkins
to get into this sandwich.
See how he sets it up vague
at the beginning?
He's not really talking
about the food.
He's just bringing you
into the moment.
And then
you dig in to the sandwich.
Mm-mm-mm-mm.
Ohh.
God, that's good stuff
right there.
Good job.
Really good job.
You're gonna love this.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
What do you do?
Everybody makes
pulled pork.
I'm a therapist.
Yes, you are.
Tell me about your mom.
Oh, God,
now you're therapisting me.
Therapisting you?
Yes, I coined that word.
Time out.
Is that a real word --
therapisting?
No, it's not.
Thank you very much.
I might just now bring my
English teacher with me.