Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Live from New York!
...it ain't no skit...
What up?
...just a taste
of New York City.
All right,
this is now obscene.
In Astoria, Queens...
Flavor town.
Flavor town!
Wow.
...the funky indie diner,
dedicated to doing it right.
I'm gonna have to back
for another round of hot yoga.
On the Lower East
of Manhattan...
Wow, look at this thing.
...one man's mission
to go local...
You're that hardcore?
...is paying off big time.
That is an enormous
roast-pork dinner in a sandwich.
And in Eureka, California...
I used to get spanked
with something like this
when I was a little kid.
Me too. Me too.
...an authentic slice of NYC...
When you can hold it
with one finger
and it doesn't buckle,
that's legit.
...served up
next to a serious Sicilian.
Little more girth to it.
Mm-hmm.
Just what I need.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm right over the bridge
from Manhattan
in Astoria, Queens.
You remember Astoria --
we went and visited The Sparrow?
Anyhow, you want to talk about
an area with a lot of history
and a lot of character,
this is it.
And speaking of characters, wait
till you check out this joint.
I hear it's off the hook.
This is Queens Comfort.
Captain Crunch chicken fingers,
table 11.
It's just mind blowing.
The Egg Mc'Ruffin.
I love it.
This is great.
Brisket mac and cheese,
table six.
The food here is unmatched.
Donnie makes it work
fantastically.
This is Donnie D'Alessio.
Double "D."
Nice to meet you.
[ Laughs ]
What up?
FIERI:
A cat from Queens who traded
in his low-budget film career
to open up this joint in 2011.
And he's had a "Triple D"
drive-by on his mind ever since.
This is
my dream come true.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Are you married, Donnie?
Um...
[ Laughs ]
Okay, I'm not married yet.
I've been in a relationship
for five years
and I just recently bought
a ring,
but I haven't proposed yet.
Very nice.
Probably 'cause he's had
his hands full
coming up with the out-of-bounds
dishes
that keeps this place packed.
This is like
an eclectic-funk menu.
Enchiladas and burgers
and comfort food.
D'ALESSIO:
Chicken and waffles.
Anything you can imagine.
FIERI:
Or Donnie can imagine.
And he's digging deep
for inspiration
on this Queens Comfort classic.
Down by Law, table six.
Down by Law chicken sandwich
is amazing.
It's one of
my favorite movies.
It's about
these three characters
that end up in a jail cell.
That was the inspiration
for the sandwich.
We're using like a bunch
of different elements in there.
So, we're gonna smoke
these chicken breasts.
This thing
looks like it's new.
Where did you learn
to smoke meat?
I just read the instructions
when I bought it.
[ Laughs ]
How long
are these gonna smoke?
Two hours.
So,
let's get into the bacon jam.
First we'll add the onions.
These are caramelized onions.
Bacon.
Now we're just gonna blend
this stuff together.
Now we're gonna make
the rest of the bacon jam.
Add water, sugar.
We're gonna let that
caramelize,
and then we're gonna add
the bacon and the onions.
That's like pig napalm
right there.
[ Laughs ]
So, we're gonna let that reduce
for like 30 minutes.
Now we're gonna make the braise
for the smoked chicken.
Start with orange juice,
pineapple juice, soy sauce,
sesame oil, honey, molasses,
Sriracha, brown sugar, bacon.
So, whisk that together.
Okay.
And we're gonna cover
the chicken.
Wrap it some foil. How long
is it gonna go in the oven?
About 40 minutes.
350?
Yep.
This is the type
of chicken or turkey
that you would buy
in the supermarket.
Then we're gonna bring it out
and we're gonna press it.
FIERI: Which, to get it right,
takes over night.
Now it's compact.
Okay.
And now we're gonna slice it.
Now we're gonna slice it.
What is this?
[ Chuckles ]
It sounds like my boy Chico
getting dental work.
Just like that.
The worse piece
of kitchen equipment
I have ever seen on "Triple D,"
right here.
But the segment isn't over yet,
so, you know...
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna heat it
in the braise.
In some of the jus.
Yeah,
so the flavors are there.
We're gonna jam.
Slice of cheddar.
Under the salamander?
Under the broiler?
Yeah.
All right, it's ready.
We got
our chipotle aioli here.
Homemade aioli and chipotle.
Some bibb lettuce.
All right.
We got the chicken.
Supermarket chicken!
Bacon jam and cheddar.
What a sandwich, dude.
Avocado.
Close this up, here.
I just want to see
what this looks like.
Look at that.
Huh?
This is outstanding.
There is so much flavor
going on in that,
it is ridiculous.
The smokiness,
the brine, the salty.
The braise is what makes it.
The crazy press...
The thin slice of the chicken
changes that texture --
sandwich is off the chain,
dude.
Flavor town.
Nicely done.
Flavor town. Wow!
Literally
the most tender chicken breast
I've ever had in my life.
I can drink the bacon jam.
I mean, it brings you
back to your childhood.
A little bit of nostalgia.
It makes you feel
like you're a kid again.
MAN: All the pictures
on the wall made you feel like
you were at your aunt's house --
your aunt that could cook
really good.
Atomic Fire Balls.
FIERI: Plus, he's making
the kind of unique food
that only a kid could dream up.
I got the Atomic Fire Balls.
It's like homemade mac
and cheese scooped into a ball.
They're atomic, but they're
really, really, really good.
Yo!
So, now we're making
the Atomic Fire Balls.
Okay.
All kinds of cheese.
We got the Béchamel, here.
This is milk and cream.
When are
you gonna get engaged?
Oh,
a couple years from now.
Man, I wouldn't wait around
on that one. Okay, we good?
Garlic powder.
Okay.
Onion powder.      Onion powder.
Cayenne.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Tabasco.
Texas Pete.
Wow, this is spicy.
Sriracha.
Shredded yellow cheddar.
White cheddar.
Yeah.
Shredded fontina cheese.
All right,
so we're gonna whisk this...
Okay.
So, that's that.
We're gonna add heavy cream
and the egg yolks.
Gonna whisk that in.
Elbow macaroni.
Pour it into a hotel pan
and let it set.
That looks
like it's gonna be a mess.
Try this.
Mmm! That is spicy, though.
Whoo!
Parchment.
Let it set up,.
So, now we're gonna make
the egg wash. Eggs, here.
Tabasco.
Texas Pete.
Sriracha.
That's ready to go.
All right, so, now we have
our flour, panko.
Now we're gonna make
the balls.
Scoop the macaroni.
Form it.
Now you go into the flour,
into the egg wash...
Yeah. Into the panko,
which we also have --
And the panko
is seasoned with...?
Cayenne.
You deep fry it.
So,
they're out of the fryer.
You get five per order.
This is the garnish.
Oh, geez.
All right,
this is now obscene.
Mmm! Aw!
I'm gonna have to go back
for another round of hot yoga.
[ Laughs ]
That's crazy.
Typically, when you have mac
and cheese balls, they're dry.
But the fact that you had
that Béchamel so thick,
you fried them quickly,
you made them small enough
so the heat could get
all the way through
without cooking
all the cheese out.
These things
are bangin', dude.
Well done.
Pow!
Fire Balls ready.
It's like my mom's mac and
cheese but with a kick to it.
Clear your sinuses right up.
It's just a great thing to have
in the neighborhood.
Being on this show
has been a dream come true.
It would also be
a dream come true if...
Jill Sirota,
will you marry me?
Yes, of course!
[ Applause ]
[ Laughs ]
Engaged today on "Triple D."
Never seen that coming,
baby!
FIERI: Up next...
That's ridiculous.
...we're headed
to Manhattan's East Village...
Oh,
that's gonna be terrible.
[ Chuckles ]
...where one rock-star chef
meets another.
Mmm.
This is like a pig under
an apple tree in the grass.
...over one serious sandwich.
That's outrageous.
I'm here in New York City,
right down
on the Lower East Side,
almost by Chinatown.
Now, typically when I'm coming
down here,
I'm looking for a sandwich,
going to one of my favorite
joints, and that's Katz's Deli.
But I hear that over here
on Orchard Street,
there's a chef that has got
a 300-mile farm-to-table thing
going on.
You know
I got to check this out.
This is Black Tree.
Give me two lambs, two pig,
and a short rib.
Such unique ingredients.
It's all about what's fresh
and what's available.
Caesar with a side of Brussels
sprouts right there.
So, these dudes, small, little
business here in New York,
this meatball-shop thing.
What do you guys got,
90 locations now?
Five locations.
So,
you cats recommended this.
Yeah.
Sandy's the man.
The sandwich is delicious.
Just gangster.
So, anytime anybody comes in the
city, we send people over here.
FIERI:
High praise for chef Sandy Dee,
who turned
this former leather-goods store
into a 30-seater back in 2013.
Winter Pig up, side kale.
His mission --
upscale on the downlow.
You never really know
what's gonna be on the menu.
It's always a surprise
and it's always good.
I'm having the Winter Pig.
It is a bit of a flavor
explosion in your mouth.
So, we're gonna make
the spice rub right now
for the pig sandwich.
First, I'm gonna put in
some of this coffee grounds.
Salt.
Brown sugar.
Some Aleppo pepper.
This is kind of the main...
Aleppo pepper!
I love Aleppo pepper.
There you go.
Awesome.
I like 'cause it's
like a little spice,
but it has, like,
a smokey flavor.
We're gonna mix this up.
Then, I put some
in the bottom,
so there's like a little mat
for the pork belly.
Then I'm just gonna lay in
the belly.
Then we're gonna add
some more spice rub in on top.
What liquid are we using
to braise this in?
I actually braise this in beer.
Oh,
that's gonna be terrible.
[ Laughs ]
I can't use anything that's not
local,
so I have no citrus here,
like lemons, limes,
anything like that.
Time out!
[ Buzzer sounds ]
Are you serious?
Yeah.
You're that hardcore?
Next, we're gonna add
our Sixpoint IPA
and Peekskill's sour,
which has
this hyper-lemon twang at the
end and it really comes through.
In the oven, 275,
two and a half hours?
Yeah.
Got it.
What's our next step?
I'm gonna pickle some apples.
So, I start with hot peppers.
Apple cider vinegar.
Cinnamon. Bay leaves.
Star anise.
Celery seed.
Juniper berries.
Coriander seeds.
Cloves.
Should we just go along
the idea of saying
you took every dry spice
you have?
[ Laughs ]
I did. Anise seed.
Ani-- Geez.
Celery seed.
And then
some brown sugar at the end
so you get a little spicy/sweet
balance in there.
Bring it to a boil, then let it
simmer 20, 25 minutes.
Then we'll pop the apples in?
Yeah.
What's our next step?
So, we're gonna do
the brown-butter apple preserves
for the pig sandwich.
Got it.
So, we're gonna start off
with some butter, brown sugar.
The apples in
and then I'll put cold water in
and I'll put more sugar in
and then some salt over top.
Then we give it some spins
and just kind of let it cook.
Let it cook down.
Yep.
So, it'll take about
an hour and half to two hours.
Okay.
This is the pork belly,
it's been cooking in the oven.
That's ridiculous.
So, I'm gonna slice
the pork belly first.
So,
I'm gonna take this bread.
I use micro-ciabatta
for everything.
And then I'm gonna add the
brown-butter apple preserves.
Then we're gonna take our
cheddar, kind of layer that on.
Now I'm gonna pop this
in the broiler.
Next, I'm gonna add some
pickled apples over the cheddar.
Take some of my pork belly...
Put a lot on there
for you.
And then the fresh mint.
Wow, look at this thing.
[ Chuckles ]
That's outrageous.
The sweet apple jam
counters the saltiness.
Oh, my God.
Then the bright,
fresh mint --
that is
an enormous roast-pork dinner,
all the fixings,
in a sandwich.
Out of bounds, man.
Thank you.
Winter Pig up.
Like a nice, fine-dining dish,
with just this wonderful hero
kind of wrapped on it.
Do you know
Alex Guarnaschelli?
DEE: Yes. Yes.
I invited Chef
to come down here
because this is
in her attitude about food.
Let's get her a sandwich,
man.
So, there you go.
This is really beautiful,
and it smells so good.
[ Slurps ]
Mmm.
[ Growls ]
This is like a pig under
an apple tree in the grass.
I mean, that's basically
what we have here.
I think it's great.
Look at this, in 300 miles,
sticking true to his mantra.
Pretty remarkable.
That's why I thought
you would appreciate it.
And from somebody so young.
I have a lot of respect
for your focus.
I have something different
every single time,
'cause I know it's gonna be
consistent and delicious.
The food's fantastic,
and the fact
that you complement it
with the farm-to-table attitude
is righteous.
Nice job, Sandy.
Thanks.
Crazy.
Bring a towel.
Boom.
FIERI: Coming up...
[ Whistles ]
...we're headed
to Eureka California
to get a couple of slices...
FIERI:
This is, without question,
in the top five best
Margherita pizzas I've ever had.
...of some true New York pie.
So, I'm here
in Eureka, California.
Now, back in the day
when I was a kid,
that theater, that was it, man.
Then,
the big mall comes into town,
and they start getting
all the first-run movies.
This area kind of slows down.
Well, that's
until this joint shows up,
where this dude is doing
old-school,
real-deal, New-York-style pies.
This is Paul's
Live From New York.
It's beyond good.
The first time I had
New-York-style pizza was here.
Bliss in a bite.
How's the basil looking?
It's, like,
being made by an artist.
FIERI: Picasso of the pie
Paul Amato --
a totally legit pie maker who
came all the way from Jersey...
Boom.
...and opened this joint in '05.
I didn't know New-York pizza
until these guys came to town.
You guys work at a pizza joint,
at Ferndale Pizza Co.
What makes this so dynamite?
The simplicity of the sauce
and the thinness.
The crust is the heart
of the matter.
FIERI:
'Cause that's where it starts
no matter what kind of pie
you're getting.
Margherita pizza's great.
FIERI: What are we gonna do?
The pizza dough
for our 18-inch pies.
Start off with the water.
All right.
Here's the salt.
Then, sugar.
Hey, kids, tub's ready!
50-pound bag of flour.
Olive oil.
The yeast,
I will crumble that on top,
and then we'll put the hook
in there.
Here we go.
So, we're gonna let this go
for about 10 minutes.
About 10 minutes.
Let it rest for two days.
And then,
we're ready for service.
Rock solid.
Got it.
Yep.
FIERI:
Okay, so, let's get this going.
Make a little edge.
This makes a nice crust.
A little edge?
That holds water, baby.
Well, it's like pottery --
like baking pottery.
And the elasticity
of that high-gluten flour,
this thing is gonna
[Exhales sharply]
Whoa!
is this a 24" you're making?
This is the 18".
Dude, there is no way
that's only 18".
What do you put a 24" on?
That one.
There's the big one.
I used to get spanked
with something like this
when I was a little kid.
Me, too. Me, too.
[ Chuckles ]
That's huge.
Here we go.
What the...are you doing?
Chunks and splatters.
Mozzarella chunks.
Oof. I'm out of here.
[ Chuckles ]
I can't watch any of this.
Roasted garlic.
Okay.
[ Whistles ]
And the raw garlic.
Pecorino romano.
In we go. Okay.
Beautiful.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
See, I like
how the chunks melted.
[ Crust crunches ]
Listen to the crust crunch
on the bottom of that thing.
A little basil.
And a little romano.
Look at that.
Oh!
That fresh basil right on top,
the little saltiness
of that pecorino romano
coming over the top.
Dude!
The key on this one,
brother,
having the two levels
of the garlic in there.
Out of bounds, man.
That is way beyond
the average margherita pizza.
This is, without question,
in the top-five best
margherita pizzas I've ever had.
Excellent.
This margherita pizza
is delicious.
MAN #2: Cooked perfectly
and the big cloves of garlic
and, of course, the thin crust.
It's the only
New-York-style pizza in town.
FIERI: And while Paul
is altering the way
a lot of locals
are looking at pizza,
he's also fixing
to try to change the way
I think about thick-crust pie...
If you don't like deep dish,
you'll still dig this.
...when we come back.
FIERI:
Triple D's at a joint called
Paul's Live From New York.
It's in Eureka, California,
where they're cranking out
real-deal, old-school,
authentic east-coast pie.
Second to none.
FIERI: I mean, round and thin
is definitely in,
but that doesn't mean that
square and stout is totally out.
The Sicilian pizza,
the crust is thicker.
FIERI:
Probably so it can handle
a truckload
of homemade mozzarella.
Now, what is a Sicilian?
It's a square pan.
We making focaccia?
No.
Don't make me eat focaccia
with pizza toppings.
Nope. Nope.
Sicilian all the way.
All right.
There we go.
So, you got a little bit of oil
on there,
heavy,
almost cast-iron-like pan.
Put a little bit of that
on there.
A little tomato sauce with
a little bit of water in it.
Gives it a little color,
and it keeps it from drying out.
Okay. So, now you take this,
and it goes into the proof?
Proofer.
Then, you make the pie?
Yeah.
SO, we've proofed.
Now I'm gonna take some zucchini
and some squash.
Roasted garlic on there.
A little splash
of the marinara sauce.
Throw it in,
it's gonna cook halfway.
Yeah,
just like you're baking bread
'cause it's gonna take that long
'cause it's focaccia bread.
Looks good.
Yep.
There's the mozz you made.
Put that on there.
It's nice and crusty.
It's not soft
like normal focaccia.
No. It's a different type
of focaccia.
Is it?
[ Laughs ]
I'll admit it now. I'll admit
it. I can't stand it.
Romano cheese,
a little olive oil.
So, in with the focaccia.
All right.
[ Laughs ]
How long
is that gonna go?
Probably eight minutes.
FIERI: Look at that.
That's crazy.
Dude.
Look at the size
of this thing.
The more the better.
I was just telling you,
when you can hold it like that
and it doesn't fold up,
that's legit.
It's not super doughy
and mushy in the middle.
The bread sat there
on that thick pizza pan
with a little bit of oil,
and it literally fried
the bottom of this.
So, it is so crispy,
so crunchy.
This is a cross between a really
nice Neapolitan-style pizza
with a little more girth
to it -- just what I need.
Mmm.
You kill it, man.
Thanks, bro.
Excellent thick crust,
lots of veggies.
We can each get the kind of
pizza that we want and be happy.
This is my buddy
Shane Lewis.
We played Little League
together.
I've known this guy forever.
What did you think of the pie?
It's outstanding,
and it's great.
Best pizza is Humboldt County.
And they're putting this
together for you.
That's what makes this place
really good.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diner's, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
[ Applause ]
It's crazy.
Do you see the tear?
Actually,
I got a little tear.
When he gave you the ring
and you started to cry,
I'm like, "Oh!"