Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
O-m-g.
...release the jaw...
I'm so full from eating it,
and I want more.
...'cause we're dishing out
some righteous bites...
It sounds like an extra
45 minutes on the elliptical.
It is.
...in Los Angeles, California.
This is not even
humanly possible.
The monster of all sandwiches...
This is ridiculous,
by the way.
...jam-packed
with the good stuff.
Cheese sticks,
Philly cheesesteak,
French fries,
chicken fingers.
Then up the coast in Monterey...
I don't use
this fancy-dancy stuff.
...we're hitting the wharf...
This is like calamari
gone wild.
...for some
off-the-hook seafood.
Wow. This is fresh.
Mmm!
And in Aiea, Hawaii...
I mean, I think I got
a pretty wild hairstyle.
But I think you might take
the cake, buddy.
...some
out-of-this-world flavor...
This is crazy good.
...at a place known
for serving up strikes.
In a bowling alley?
Are you kidding me?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here in Los Angeles
in Westwood Village,
just a couple blocks from UCLA.
But how did I get here,
is the story.
See, I got this buddy named Jay
that lives on the East Coast.
He says, "Hey, Guy.
Next time you go to Los Angeles,
"you got to check out this East
Coast buddy of mine's joint
that he opened up.
You're gonna love it."
I said, "Really?"
And he says, "Would I send you
anywhere else?"
All right.
This is Fat Sal's.
Fat Bahn Mi-ki!
You'll never try
another sandwich
like this anywhere else.
Waiting on the Reuben rolls.
Chili cheeseburger.
It's crazy.
MAN: They take the appetizers
and the French fries
and they put them
on the actual sandwich itself.
FIERI: Serving up
monster sandwiches
is the brainchild
of owners Josh Stone,
Sal Capnick, and Jerry Ferrara,
three New York buddies
who invaded
health-conscious Cali
with their greasy-spoon concept.
We couldn't find the kind
of food that we wanted to eat.
So we were just like,
"Whatever.
Let's just make it
all ourselves."
And since they opened in 2010,
their cravings have caught on.
You bring somebody from the East
Coast that's out here visiting,
will you bring them here?
I always do.
Take them
to the Hollywood sign,
take them
to the walk of fame,
take them to Fat Sal's.
MAN: I'm not gonna lie.
The only reason
I come to Westwood
is for Fat Sal's sandwiches.
I have no idea
what else is here.
Fat Jerry.
WOMAN:
I'm having the Fat Jerry.
And it's just like,
the best thing I've ever had.
So, this is the Fat Jerry.
This is the Fat Jerry.
Named after...
Jerry Ferrara.
FIERI: Yep.
That'd be Jerry,
a.k.a. Turtle,
from HBO's "Entourage."
Everybody that's
in movies or TV
wants to be
in the restaurant business.
Everybody in sports
wants to be
in the restaurant business.
Everybody in
the restaurant business...
Wants to be in...
Movies and sports.
All right, so let's go.
Starts with
our extra-wide hero bread,
which we call fat bread.
Okay.
Give this thing
a little bit of that butter.
Get it started
on the grill.
Okay.
We're gonna drop
chicken fingers,
mozzarella sticks,
and French fries.
Oh, what else
is going in this?
Bacon.
Eggs.
Cheesesteak.
Onions.
All for one sandwich?
All for one sandwich.
Little bit of salt,
little bit of pepper.
I'm gonna give this
a little turn.
I'm gonna chop up
our Philly.
We got a little American cheese
going on here.
Bacon.
We're gonna take this.
Philly cheesesteak,
an egg.
Okay.
That thing's looking good.
Chicken fingers,
mozzarella sticks.
And fries.
This is not even
humanly possible.
We're gonna do
a little bit of ketchup,
a little bit of mayo.
This is ridiculous,
by the way.
This goes here.
This goes there.
Look at the gour-met
in you.
Yep.
I'm gonna give this
a nice roll, nice cut.
Look at this thing.
Cheese sticks,
Philly cheesesteak,
French fries,
chicken fingers.
Bacon.
Oh, and --
There's bacon.
No lettuce,
none of that --
We're not screwing it up
and over-vegetablizing it,
you know?
It's legit, Josh.
Little nostalgia.
Nice job, my friend.
Thanks, brother.
Fat Jerry!
MAN: I'm indecisive,
so I like to take all
the things I might want,
have it all
on the same sandwich.
And you would think that
it would be just weird,
but it's really amazing.
It kind of makes me feel young,
eating something like this.
Who came up with things
like the Fat Jerry,
which is far away
from the truth?
JERRY: I pig out.
When we were going
through the Fat Jerry,
I just couldn't believe
that you guys
would let me put all
this stuff on a sandwich.
[ Laughter ]
But the menu's rocking
more than just sandwiches.
All right. So, what
are we gonna make, man?
We are going to make
meat lovers' pizza rolls
with a marinara-sauce dip.
For some reason,
it sounds like
an extra 45 minutes
on the elliptical.
It is.
It could be.
At times.
Depends how many you eat.
Give me the rundown,
boss.
Okay.
So, we're gonna mix all
of our stuff together here.
We've got our ground beef,
sausage, chopped-up pepperoni,
parmesan,
shredded mozzarella,
and chopped provolone.
Fresh basil.
Then we're gonna add a little
bit of the marinara sauce.
We are going to have to
put on these.
All right.
Oh.
This is how they go on.
Fast.
I'm ready.
Oh, I really thought
you had that thing on.
I'm like,
"Guy's a professional."
So, we're gonna give this
a mix.
All right.
She's a-mixed.
Spring-roll wrapper.
There we go.
A little
measuring device.
Little egg wash.
Little egg.
I'm gonna tuck
and roll here.
Put it in a little flour.
And hold them cold.
Yeah.
We are going to...
Drop them like they're...
Hot.
MAN: Hot.
Okay.
Nice, nice.
Sexy.
Nice crunch.
Take a look at that.
Mmm!
Great flavor.
I get that pepperoni,
not too much cheese,
which is what
I was worried about.
Awesome crunch
from the roll.
You got a lot
of texture to it.
It doesn't sog out on you.
I should just try
one more.
Just a little bit.
Mmm.
Meat lover pizza rolls!
Literally pizza in an egg roll.
It's fantastic.
The meat lovers' pizza rolls
remind me of New York.
When I told you about that buddy
of mine on the East Coast,
that's my buddy
right there.
His name's Jay,
and he's a buddy of Jerry's.
So, fitting that
I get you two here.
Jerry and I
are East Coast guys,
so, it's, like, nice to
have something East Coast.
Nice recommendation, my brother.
Hey, what can
I get you today?
Hi.
If you come to L.A.
and you're visiting me,
we're going to Fat Sal's.
You want to finish that?
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna crush that.
I'm gonna crush it
right now.
Up next, I'm cruising
to Monterey...
Salt, pepper.
Lime zest.
Done.
Check!
...for a fresh-catch joint
that's reeling in
one favorite...
I'm an abalone junkie.
...after another.
Dungeness crab, to me,
is the king of the sea.
I'm here
in Monterey, California,
on Municipal Wharf 2.
Now, this is the working wharf.
There's a tourist wharf
on that side.
But this is where the boats
really come in.
I mean, you got an abalone farm
down there,
you got a fish market,
you name it.
And you need a place
for the wharf workers to eat.
And that's right here
at this joint,
Loulou's Griddle in the Middle.
This is really good food.
Fish tacos.
Oh, great.
It's my favorite place to come.
It's almost like dancing
in the aisles.
It's time to party.
FIERI:
A party that started in 2001
when Loulou Garrett
bought the joint.
And 10 years later, her business
partner, Gigi Davis,
jumped ship from corporate life
to join the fun.
This is now my office,
which I feel
incredibly grateful for.
Really stressful.
I don't know.
You must have a real good
therapy plan here.
This super-chill spot used to be
a bait shop back in '48.
And it's still keeping up
that fresh-catch tradition.
Halibut over
mixed baby greens.
...hauling in one
of my favorites, abalone.
Fresh is the best.
And it's actually farmed and
grown right here in the bay.
Crazy.
These bad boys are amazing.
They're not like calamari.
They're not like clams.
They're like something
you've never had before.
A little more buttery
than calamari.
Yeah, more buttery.
Fattier than calamari.
GARRETT: Abalone sliders.
They are so delicate
and flavorful
and probably the perfect slider.
I'm an abalone junkie.
Abalone is the jewel
of the Pacific North coast.
It is.
Okay, get after it.
Okay.
We're gonna make the dredge
for the abalone sliders.
Flour, white pepper.
Okay.
Garlic salt.
Got it.
All Seasoned salt.
Cayenne. Paprika.
That's it. Simple.
Don't be afraid
that she put that much Cayenne
in there.
It's not
super-spicy Cayenne.
No.
It's not gonna hurt you.
Let's do it.
Aren't they beautiful?
Wrecking his day.
Yep, right there.
Done.
Okay. Now we're gonna
take the body off.
Wow, this is fresh.
Yes.
Okay, here we go.
So, we finish the little finish
of the tenderizing.
Not so much that
you broke all the flesh
'cause you want it
to have its texture.
Take those out. We're gonna
just dredge them up.
Great.
Got our pan heating here.
I'm gonna put the buns down
'cause it's gonna cook super
quick, less than a minute.
High heat.
Little clarified butter
there.
Just enough to warm them up
and put a crust on them.
Pretty much.
This is like calamari
gone wild.
You do not want
to overcook them.
We're gonna make the aioli.
I'll do the mayo.
Okay.
Go 'cause I don't want
that abalone to overcook.
Lime juice.
Mayo, lime juice, check.
We have an olive oil that's been
infused with lemongrass.
Very nice.
Fresh cilantro.
Salt, pepper.
Lime zest.
Check!
Check on those abalones.
Get it good.
That enough?
That's enough.
Abalone slider.
Put a little slaw
on there.
That's a little radish,
cilantro.
Got that.
Fruit slaw.
It's so tender.
Great abalone flavor.
Not too much spice.
The bun fits it well.
I mean, I love any great
sourdough bun like this.
Slaw complements it.
All the bright, fresh flavors
with the crunch --
it's fantastic.
Great.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Mmm!
That's good abalone.
The spices are blended
perfectly together.
How do you explain
the seafood
that you get here
at Loulou's?
It's so fresh.
MAN: And the boat pulls up
right to the back
of the restaurant.
You watch it get unloaded.
You can't beat that.
FIERI: And they're pulling in
this hands-on favorite.
GARRETT: Crab feast.
When crab season comes around,
everybody gets excited
because we know we're gonna have
a good meal that night.
From November 2nd
to right around June...
GARRETT: Yep.
...you can get fresh
dungeness crab.
And dungeness crab, to me,
is the king of the sea.
So how do you do yours?
Simple.
Sea salt.
Bay leaves.
Couple lemons.
We're just gonna drop
the whole lemon in there.
Garlic. That's it.
So a simple seasoning
to it,
not too much stealing
from the flavor.
Yep.
Look at that.
Upside-down.
Buh-bye.
Wait till you see how vibrant
orange it's gonna turn.
Okay. How long you gonna
have it down?
About 15, 20 minutes.
Ready?
Bring it.
You take the shell,
clean out the mustard,
and do all that.
Yes.
Unless they ask for it.
Unless they want the yum-yum.
They might.
We just put that top shell
on just to...
Just 'cause
you want to make --
Just 'cause it's beautiful.
Corn. Potato.
Parsley. Butter.
Lemon.
Now, at my house, I don't use
this fancy-dancy stuff.
I just get that fork right in
there, just rip it right open.
That's how I get after it.
Little bit of lemon.
Crab.
[ Sighs ]
The natural flavor of the
dungeness crab is outrageous.
Sweet.
And it's buttery,
it's sweet, it's tender.
The key to this is...
you didn't mess with it.
No.
You just treat it
with respect.
Little respect.
Cook it the right way,
serve it hot.
More lemon.
Outrageous.
Creamy and buttery,
delicious.
Wouldn't mind getting messy
for this crab at all.
Fun joint and I can see
why you're so successful.
That boat-to-table attitude
is alive and well.
Awesome.
Thank you so much.
FIERI: Up next...
[ Growls ]
...a bowling alley
in Aiea, Hawaii...
I'm shaking.
I can't get it in the spoon.
...rolling out
the righteous oxtail.
I want to get in the bowl.
I'm about four miles
from the Honolulu airport
in a little community
known as Aiea.
Now, I have been hearing
for years,
"You've got to check
this joint out.
"You got to try this.
You got to try that.
"But you got to try
the oxtail soup.
I mean, it's off the hook."
All right.
I show up.
It's in a bowling alley?
Are you kidding me?
This is The Alley Restaurant.
[ Pins clatter ]
Here's your
furikake ahi plate.
This is not your average
bowling food.
Your tasty chicken plate.
When you see the guys
in the kitchen,
they're wearing chef uniforms,
right?
You don't see that
in a bowling alley.
FIERI:
And chef/owner Glenn Uyeda
has got some serious game.
I mean, I think I got
a pretty wild hairstyle.
But I think you might take
the cake, buddy.
How long you been doing
your hair that way?
20-something years.
Seriously?
You're awesome.
[ Laughs ]
Well, you have more claim
to fame on it than I do, then.
Yeah, it looks like this chef's
all about doing his own thing.
Just a dream of mine to have
a nice restaurant and good food.
So he picked up some skills
working on another island.
Two years,
I worked in New York City.
And since he opened
this joint in 2005,
word's definitely got around.
I was on the airplane
on my way here.
And the flight attendants were
telling me about this place
and about the oxtail soup.
The oxtail soup
is out of this world.
You can't find anything better.
UYEDA: Oxtail soup up.
I've heard from everybody
the oxtails here
are the best on the island.
What makes them so awesome?
My mother's recipe.
My mom has a beautiful sauce
with it.
All right.
Well, let's get into it.
We're gonna
just add the meat.
You want to start
with cold water.
Yep.
'Cause you want to get
the impurities out.
And when it comes up
to a boil, it's done.
That's a key part
of making good oxtail.
Then we'll drain it,
rinse it,
and then that's when
we start the process.
That's when
Got it.
First we're gonna put in
some dried dates.
Dried dates.
Dried...
Orange peel.
...orange peel.
Star anise.
Dig it.
Special ginger, whole.
Raw peanuts.
Lot of work, man.
We do 150 orders a day.
[ Record scratches ]
How many orders a day?
150.
Of oxtails?
Yes.
Do you have anything else
on the menu?
No.
Yes, we do.
Yes. No.
Dried shiitake.
Okay.
That's a big flavor piece
to this dish.
We have chicken
and beef stock.
Then you're gonna fill it all
the way in here till it covers.
As soon as it boils,
we're gonna turn it down
to a simmer for three hours.
Do we drink the Jack
while we're waiting?
Jack is gonna go in
at the end.
Into who?
Into this soup.
You can have some, as well.
That's a buzzkill.
We're gonna make the sauce.
This is the sauce?
This is the sauce
that goes with it.
Soup gets sauce?
The sauce is the best thing
about the dish.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Daikon radish.
We're making radish juice.
So we're gonna add
the pulp in here.
Soy sauce.
I love soy sauce.
Lemon juice,
fresh-squeezed.
Sesame seed oil,
a key ingredient.
Red chili peppers.
And to top it off is a little
toasted sesame seed.
Then we mix it all up.
And this is the sauce that
we dip this whole thing in.
Ooh.
Got a little bite.
That's delicious.
We're gonna finish the soup
with a little
Tennessee whisky.
Here we go.
No wonder everybody
in this island loves you.
You could feed your
whole family with this.
Here we go.
We're gonna be adding
some baby bok choy
and the green onions.
Ginger and cilantro
or Chinese parsley,
and you add that --
As you like.
O-m-g.
This is not gonna be good.
I'm gonna be asleep
in the parking lot.
A little bit
of mom's sauce.
It will cut that.
Oh!
Dude, you win best oxtail soup
in the world award.
This is crazy good.
That was the bite
right there.
What I can't get over
is the flavor in the broth.
And then you get
that mom sauce.
I'm shaking.
I can't get it in the spoon.
It's hot.
I want to shove it in my face.
I want to get in the bowl.
Mmm!
[ Growls ]
MAN: And here we have
our oxtail soup.
Very beefy flavor.
It has a lot of oxtail in it.
A little spice, a little
sweetness, little tartness.
Just wonderful.
The ponzu sauce is a nice
addition on the side.
It's crazy.
It is.
I'm so full from eating it,
and I want more.
At The Alley Restaurant,
it's not just oxtail stew.
No.
You have more.
We have more.
Like what?
Barbecue --
Don't!
Actually, don't tell me.
Okay, here's the deal.
We're hanging out at the
Aiea Bowling Alley in Aiea
at The Alley Restaurant.
When we come back,
I'll be asleep
and Chef will make
something else.
I'm gonna finish this.
Bomb.
FIERI:
So, here I am in Aiea, Hawaii,
and the locals have steered me
to this joint --
a bowling alley?
It's called
The Alley Restaurant
and it's here in the town of
Aiea right outside of Waikiki.
This guy made an oxtail stew
that is out of this world.
But he promises me he has more
tricks up his sleeve.
Chef, what do we got?
We're gonna make
some cola turkey.
Cola, like regular cola
that everybody likes?
Cola.
Okay.
We're gonna start off
with a fresh turkey breast.
And we're gonna make it
into portions
that we're gonna
be marinating.
Put it into our pot here.
Let's make the marinade.
Cola is what
we're gonna start with.
Just straight off the tap.
And then we're gonna do
a little salad oil.
Soy sauce.
Fresh garlic.
Fresh ground pepper.
Watch the cola.
Once I turn it in here,
it's gonna change,
it's gonna get
all bubbly like that.
Okay.
And that cola will tenderize
this turkey.
It's gonna taste like beef
if you close your eyes.
No.
Yes.
Really?
You're gonna say, "Oh,
what is that beef?"
But it's turkey.
And how long are we gonna let
this marinate on the turkey?
Overnight.
All right.
So, this is our
overnight-marinated turkey.
And we will grill some.
How many pieces
do you get?
Three.
We have to turn it and turn it
so it doesn't burn.
And here we have our turkey
right off the grill.
All that's gonna go
on that bun?
in this bun.
Put some mayonnaise
in here, both sides.
I'll drop this lettuce
right in here.
This is your sandwich.
I don't know exactly how
to get after this,
so I'm gonna have to
get half of it.
Mmm!
Look at the juice
coming off of that.
It doesn't taste like soda pop
and it's not super-sweet.
But that is rich flavor
all the way through
and it is super tender.
I mean, super tender.
Mmm.
It's like Thanksgiving.
I'd eat till I pass out.
That, seriously --
it's simple
and it's to the point,
but it is super flavorful.
Dynamite, Chef.
Your cola turkey sandwich.
It's not dry.
It's so moist and so tender.
It's very hearty.
You don't feel like
you're eating a sandwich.
You feel like
you're eating a meal.
Tasty chicken plate.
WOMAN: People come from all
over the island to eat here
for the food and for bowling,
but for the food.
Order up.
And the food's righteous.
I mean, this food
is ridiculously good.
Ridiculous.
Ridiculous, yes.
That's the word.
I concur.
It's not bowling-alley food.
I'll tell you that much.
The reputation is huge.
The food is legit.
You take the time,
you put it in a really funky,
fun atmosphere.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Really nice.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
It's funky.
It is money.
I think I need
one more from you.
Shut the front door.
Thank you.
[ Laughter ]
This is making my day!