Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I'm gonna blow up a fat tab
in this joint.
...we're dedicated
to keeping it real...
Break it down for me
from the beginning.
...in Midtown New York.
Rock on.
The pizza man
direct from Naples...
You don't have to worry
about ripping this recipe off.
[ Both laugh ]
...coming in hot...
Whoa!
You almost took that one
to the teeth, homey.
...and serving it up fried.
I just want to smear this
all over me.
In Eureka, California...
My mouth
is starting to water.
...the queen
of the kitchen...
Sweet Mama Janisse.
[ Snaps fingers ]
Don't you know?
...serving up
the sunny-side of soul.
So good, it makes you
want to slap your...
Mama?
And in Miami, Florida...
It's
Asian-food-plus-plus.
...it's my kind
of weird scientist...
You're a gangster.
...dishing out
the funky Asian fusion.
This is the last episode
of "Triple D."
HALES:
[ Chuckles ]
I'm dead. Goodbye.
Game over.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here
in Midtown Miami, Florida.
Oh, I love this area.
Now, it's really well-known for
this big art festival they have
in December
called Art Basel.
Tens of thousands
of people show up
from all over the world
to check it out.
And talk about people coming
from all over the world
to check something out,
I hear this place
is gonna rock the house.
This is Sakaya Kitchen.
Fire pork buns,
six wings.
Sakaya is sexy fast food.
Here are
the Papa's Egg Rolls.
It's Asian soul food.
Korean fried
chicken wings.
MAN: That's kind of
the mad-genius quality
exemplified by Chef Richard.
FIERI:
That's Chef Richard Hales,
who founded the joint in '09.
It was a little down
on its luck...
It was
a seafood restaurant,
and they were serving falafel,
yellow rice, and shish kebabs.
So, what's wrong
with that?
Nothing.
[ Laughs ]
That's
why we're here.
[ Laughing ] That's why --
That's why you got the place.
...so he opened Sakaya
with a very different plan.
We're gonna sell
a lot of wine and sake
and develop
this kind of funky fusion menu.
I just
was experimenting.
The food is incredibly unique
and well-crafted.
Duck sandwich --
It's out of this world.
Pick up duck sandwich.
The Cracklin'
Herb Duck Sandwich.
You're gonna sous-vide
some duck.
Exactly.
You're a gangster.
You start
with the raw duck legs.
Soy sauce...
brown sugar...
lemon pepper...
and then star anise,
cinnamon.
We mix this.
So, we're gonna put it
in the bag right now.
And then we just pour
the liquid in like that.
Oh, this is going to be
ridiculous.
It is ridiculous.
You want to talk about
penetration of flavor?
Suck the air out of it.
[ Machine whirs ]
We leave it in the bag,
we chill it,
we let the juices
stay with it.
We marinate it 24 hours.
We're heating this to a precise
temperature -- 82.2 Celsius.
Now you submerge
this slow --
super-slow-cook it
for seven hours.
Yes.
And then when we bring it
out of the sous-vide,
we'll cool it.
We're gonna heat it up again
because we're gonna fry it,
and this
is the fry flour.
We just start
with all-purpose flour...
paprika...
brown sugar...
granulated garlic...
black pepper, salt.
Just to make it easy on us,
we dump this in here.
Cut it open.
Look at that.
Dredge it
in the flour lightly.
And then it goes
straight into the fryer.
Three, four minutes?
Yeah.
Nice.
You're just gonna
quick-fry it
only just to put
some crust on it
and to bring it up
the temperature.
And what are we
dropping this into?
This is our
honey-orange sauce --
so star anise, cinnamon, with
honey and oranges this time.
This whole thing
comes off.
Whoa!
Who let the duck out?
Steamed potato roll there.
This is the samjang.
It's the thick, spicy
Korean ketchup made in-house
that Richard's dropping
on everything.
Our meat.
That's ridiculous.
Take a little spicy mayo --
samjang with the mayonnaise.
So, little bit
of scallions.
We make these quick pickles,
fresh cilantro.
And what is this side
that we have here?
Brussels sprouts with the really
amped-up vinaigrette --
that we use soy,
vinegar...
ginger, garlic.
[ Whipping sound ]
[ Chuckles ]
I just kung fu-ed
my palate, dude.
That is out of out bounds.
Oh!
Welcome to the culinary dojo
in Flavortown!
[ Both laugh ]
Let's get into
this sandwich.
It's deep. It's rich.
It's spicy. It's tangy.
It's silky, fresh.
It's vibrant.
It's, I mean...
That's like
my whole vocabulary.
I can't even spell
most of the words.
This is the last episode
of "Triple D."
[ Chuckles ]
That's my final meal.
I'm dead. Goodbye.
Game over.
The spices just explode
in your mouth.
Pick up
duck sandwich.
Everybody who tries it says,
"Oh, my God. This is so good.
"I'm a duck fan
all of a sudden."
I can't eat anymore. Tell me
there's nothing else, really.
One more thing
we're gonna kill you with.
Oh, come on. All right.
WOMAN: Chunk'd tots.
Chunk'd tots?
Yeah.
FIERI:
When we come back...
We're back in one of my favorite
places in the entire country.
That's right --
Miami, Florida.
But now one of my favorite
places in Miami, Florida,
is in Midtown at Sakaya.
And, Chef,
you've been blowing it up.
You're doing a Korean,
Asian-inspired,
funkalicious joint.
It's out of bounds.
FIERI: And Chef Richard's
got the inside moves
to connect with this crowd.
You have
the chunk'd tots.
The cheesy chunk'd tots
are amazing.
FIERI: Loaded with
a Korean classic, bulgogi beef.
Incredible.
Pick up chunk'd tots.
Chunk'd tots?
Yeah.
So, we're making the marinade
for the bulgogi beef.
For the bulgogi beef,
yeah.
Got it.
So, a little bit
of soy...
a little bit
of water...
little rough chop
of onions, skin on...
some fresh apples...
Seriously?
Just adding
some natural sweetness to it.
A mother lode of ginger.
Little brown sugar,
fresh garlic...
black pepper, sesame oil.
Stir that up.
And that's it?
Yeah.
Is flank steak typically
the bulgogi meat?
You can use any beef
that you really want
that you can
quick-grill.
Just as thin
as we can get it,
where you still have
a nice piece.
So,
we put our meat in,
take our marinade,
just put it right on top.
Just want to cover it.
How long is it gonna go
in the marinade?
At least six hours.
[ Sniffs ]
Oh, that's awesome.
We'll grill this and
then serve this over the
top of the chunk'd tots.
Chunk'd tots, yeah.
Word!
All right, so we got it
on the grill.
We just give it
a rough chop.
Thank you very much, 'cause
you knew I was reaching in.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm!
So, we got the tots.
They go in a bowl.
Give them a little salt
to season, samjang.
This is our spicy cheese,
so this is kind of
the secret weapon of the dish.
Scallions.
Just mix this up.
Oh, these
are ridiculous.
And now we're gonna put
the beef on it.
Samjang.
Little scallion.
[ Exhales sharply ]
It's outrageous.
The Asian flavors,
the American flavors,
the crunch, the texture.
You know what I love,
is you have
so much discipline
no matter what
you're dealing with --
a funky, little appetizer
like this.
I would weigh 450 pounds if I
lived anywhere near this place.
MAN: Chunk'd tots.
WOMAN:
It's absolutely fantastic.
It's spicy, and all the
different flavors together
just go
absolutely perfectly.
How do you explain
this place to people?
I mean, it's Asian food,
but it's Asian-food-plus-plus.
Plus-plus.
I enjoy everything about it.
I really love it.
When I come to town,
you will see me again.
I'm gonna blow up a fat tab
in this joint.
[ Chuckling ]
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
Fieri, you're late.
...we're headed
to Midtown, Manhattan
to show
a local Iron Chef...
Look at that.
Wow.
...the true taste
of Naples.
You can eat a whole pizza
and feel great.
Yeah.
So, I'm here in New York City
on 50th Street,
right between
8th and 9th Avenue.
I mean, this place is busy.
I'm here to check out
a real-deal pizza joint.
Now, when I say "real-deal,"
I'm talking from Naples.
I'm talking the owner
of this place --
I mean, he's the president
of the Association
of Neapolitan Pizza Makers!
This...
Fieri, you're late.
...is Iron Chef
Geoffrey Zakarian,
and this is Don Antonio.
I've never had pizza like this
ever in my entire life.
This pizza is as authentic
as it comes.
CAPORUSCIO:
Margherita's ready.
[ Bell dings ]
I came from Italy.
I can say that this
is one of the best pizza
that I eat in my life.
FIERI: So, when New Yorkers and
Italians swear it's the best,
you know renowned pizza master
Roberto Caporuscio
is doing it right.
Kind of helps that he was born
and raised on a dairy farm
in the heart
of Italy's pizza country,
right between
Rome and Naples.
I was cheese maker
before.
You were
a cheese maker?
Yes.
In 2012, he partnered up
with his mentor,
his don, Antonio Starita,
to school Americans
on true Neapolitan pizza.
Chef Roberto, Iron Chef
Geoffrey Zakarian, okay?
You guys know
each other?
Yeah, he was,
before, here.
Yeah, he's been
here before.
Break it down for me
from the beginning --
What makes
true Neapolitan pizza?
The most important start
for the dough.
Hit it.
Okay, water.
This is
so exciting.
I can feel
the magic.
So exciting.
Keep notes on this,
by the way.
I am.
Salt.
And we start
with a flour,
[Speaks indistinctly]
So, you're just gonna add the
flour to the water and the salt
in your own vision
and touch-by-feel?
Yes.
You don't have to worry
about ripping this recipe off.
[ Both laugh ]
This is fresh yeast.
Okay,
this is fresh yeast.
Okay, so, really, you're just
[Chuckling] looking at this...
When we started over 20 years
ago, there was no machine.
Just put that
anywhere.
You're gonna clean that.
[ Laughs ]
After that, we need to
let it rest for one hour.
Then we start making
the dough balls.
So, you're
tucking it in.
Look at that.
Looks so easy.
Pinching it off.
Wow.
Can you do it both hands?
I used to be able
to do both hands.
That's nice.
We let it rise
for at least --
between 24 and 36 hours
before using.
What is the next key step
in making true Neapolitan pizza?
The stretching part.
The stretching part?
Yes.
The method in
which you stretch it?
Yes.
Table?
Table, very, very --
no, no, no, no.
No throw?
Very delicate
because it's very soft.
Okay.
Don Antonio tell you,
you touch your dough --
look how you
touch your wife.
[ Record scratches ]
If you touch
very tough...
[ Laughter ]
Hang on a second.
I'm gonna make a note
of that one. Okay.
That gentle?
Yes.
It's always
the same size, Robert?
Yes,
all the same size.
'Cause I just went
[ Imitates whipping sound ]
It's done.
And the last component, the most
key, important piece is...?
The oven.
It comes from Naples,
a wood-fire oven -- That's all.
It's volcanic stone.
Its mouth is very small.
This dome is very low.
Cook the pizza
in one minute and a half.
And it's a good thing
it only takes a minute
because Don Antonio's
has -- Count 'em! --
60 pizzas on the menu,
including the Pizza del Papa
with butternut squash
and zucchini,
custom made
for Pope John Paul II.
And then there's this savory pie
that's literally going nuts.
This, right here, is amazing.
This is pistachio and sausage.
So, these are pistachio we
make here in-house.
Pistachio with
Parmigiano-Reggiano and oil.
[ Blender whirs ]
It's like a pesto
without garlic.
Yes.
Oh, man,
that looks good.
The sausage, we cook here
with Chianti wine.
Fresh basil...
and extra virgin oil,
of course, on top.
And fresh mozzarella.
And it go inside the oven.
Whoa!
That was scary.
You almost took that one
to the teeth, homey.
He's already ready
to turn it.
Yeah,
I check the bottom.
It's almost done.
I need to just...
That is so fast.
A little brulée
on top.
Done.
Please.
Go ahead, 'cause it's gonna be
9,000 degrees, Geoffrey.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, go ahead
and burn your mouth right off.
I don't care.
The fresh mozzarella.
And the dough.
Look at how thin
that is.
My favorite part
of wood-fired pizza
is the little char
that you get on the bottom.
It really just adds
such depth of flavor.
That action going on
with this dough is outstanding.
What do you think?
It's light.
I mean, it's just -- You can eat
a whole pizza and feel great.
Yeah.
Life-changing pizza.
Fluffy, but it's still crisp.
It's got great texture to it.
It's great.
FIERI: Great wasn't good enough
for these dudes,
so they took that crust
to the next level.
All right, guys.
Montanara Starita.
ALL: Thank you.
It's a fried pizza,
which is amazing.
Let's see it.
He's giving it the claw.
[ Whistles ]
[ Growls ]
We make a hole because
then it will be -- puff up.
How long are we gonna be
in the fryer?
35 seconds.
What temperature?
We at 350 on that?
400.
These are
the sauces now.
This, we cook with little bit
of extra virgin oil and garlic.
San Marzano tomatoes?
San Marzano.
The plum tomatoes?
Yes, the plum tomatoes.
Little basil, Parmesan.
Smoke mozzarella
comes from Italy.
Here.
Go ahead. I got it.
I got it. I got it.
Whoa!
Wow!
That is smoke.
Smoke and salt.
Mmm.
Mmm!
And now...
That's it?
...inside the oven.
How long?
For another 30 seconds.
Be careful with that thing.
He's gonna kill you.
Oh, God.
[ Laughs ]
Please.
Okay.
Smear this all over me.
[ Laughter ]
[ Muffled ] I can't get it
in my mouth fast enough.
And no grease.
Unh-unh.
Zero grease.
That's
a different level, baby.
[ Chuckling ] Who's got
the extra two pieces?
[ Laughter ]
The smoked flavor,
the crust --
I mean, you do not
leave this crust.
I'm gonna finish
all of this up.
This experience
is overwhelming.
I mean, this has been
outstanding.
Thank you very much.
Chef.
Thank you
very much.
Don't leave me hanging.
Nice job.
You got to check this out,
and while you're in town,
stop by Geoffrey's place!
He's always available.
[ Chuckling ] Did you
just throw that? Rock on.
Coming up, we're headed
to Eureka, California...
That's the soul,
baby.
...for some
serious Creole cooking.
You meet her,
you're gonna gain 20 pounds.
Of love.
So, I'm here
in Eureka, California,
right on the edge of Old Town,
to check out a joint
that says they're doing
Creole fusion.
This is Bless My Soul Cafe.
[ Bell dings ]
Yummy jambalaya!
Order up!
You can't go anywhere
and get this food.
You have to come
to Bless My Soul.
Caribbean black bean
and sausage bowl.
WOMAN: When you walk in,
you are made to feel
like you're coming to
your relatives' that you like.
Lots of love.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
Call it a Southern charm
that chef and owner
Marie Janisse Wilkins
has been blessing Nor Cal
with since 2003.
Sweet Mama Janisse.
[ Snaps fingers ]
Don't you know?
And that same kind of spice
is found in her
signature Creole dishes...
The shrimp
and crawfish étouffée.
Woman:
Oh, thank you!
It's got all the flavors.
It's excellent.
FIERI: ...that start
with an old-school family recipe
passed down
from her grandma.
We got to make
the green Creole sauce.
Bring it.
We'll start with our parsley,
green bell pepper, onions,
garlic,
fresh jalapeños.
Jalapeños!
And some fresh
green onions, babe.
I put a little bit
of oil...
some lemon juice...
Lemon juice.
....salt...
agua.
And then I turn that bad boy
off, and that's my sauce.
Now, we serve this with
how many different dishes?
I serve this with four
or five different dishes.
Whoo!
Yeah!
So good, it makes you
want to slap your...
Mama?
What are we gonna make
with this?
Shrimp
and crawfish étouffée.
Nice.
Okay, we're gonna add
some butter right here...
some onions...
Onion.
...the red bell peppers.
Now we'll add
our celery.
Isn't that
a beautiful color?
It's gorgeous.
Like me?
Oh, you --
listen...
[ Laughs ]
It can't be
that gorgeous.
And then we'll add
a little bit of garlic.
I like the way
you say "little bit,"
and then you throw in
3 tablespoons of garlic.
Next up, we're gonna put
our roux in here.
And, of course, the roux
is just flour and oil.
It puts the body and soul
into the food.
You know
what I mean?
Body and soul.
Okay, baby, what we're gonna do
now is we're gonna add some rum.
This is a little bit
of water here.
So, we just have to let it
simmer for a little bit.
When's your birthday?
January the 22nd.
[ Records scratches ]
Are you serious?
Serious.
That's my birthday.
[ Slams counter ]
My sister
from another mister.
That's right.
You have got to be
kidding me!
No, I'm not,
sweetheart.
That is crazy!
Yeah.
Now we'll get back to
finishing off this crazy dish.
All right,
my birthday sister.
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Now we're gonna add --
Some 21/25 shrimp.
That's right.
Then we'll add
the crawfish.
'Cause the crawfish
have already been cooked.
Right.
This is
that magic green sauce.
Yep, yep.
Black pepper.
A whole bunch
of thyme.
Yeah,
I think that's right.
A little bit of salt.
Are we gonna serve this
over rice?
Over
Creole-herb rice, baby.
Okay,
Creole-herb rice.
Correct.
Oh, look at
the color in this.
My mouth
is starting to water.
Well,
thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Shut the front door.
Those, uh...
crawfish are tender.
For me, it's got enough
little spice right there.
It's very rich,
very clean, very smooth.
Delicious.
Thank you.
Really good.
Nicely done.
Thank you, darling.
The étouffée is my favorite.
They definitely take their time
in preparing it,
and, you know, it's got
a lot of rich flavor in it.
So, what do you think
makes the food so good?
It's like having
your grandma make you
something killer to eat.
Your grandma
does Creole-fusion?
Not like this.
Shrimp and crawfish étouffée.
Order up.
MAN: It's the only place
in town, in this area,
that you can come
and get some food like this,
and you get a kiss and a hug
from Sweet Mama Janisse.
You meet her,
you're gonna gain 20 pounds.
Of love.
20 pounds of love.
That's what I meant.
More to love.
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm hungry.
I'm starving.
I know it doesn't look
like I am.
And I have
my Barney shirt on.
[ To the theme of
"Barney & Friends" ]
♪ I love you ♪
[ Laughter ]