I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
And this is a special edition
in my hometown
of Ferndale, California.
This trip...
I used to ride my bike
up and down these streets.
...it's a mind-blowing
cruise down memory lane...
I am just so tripping out.
...a place with lots of firsts.
This is different
than what you would think.
This goes beyond that.
...first business...
I was most well-known
for the Awesome Pretzel Cart.
...first kitchen job...
This was the kitchen line
that I cooked on.
And, I mean, I was that big.
...and you never forget
your first butcher shop.
I don't have to
clean the grinder, do I?
You're gonna have to
clean something.
Aah!
We got a bucket-list visit
to a legendary apple orchard...
This is like
a childhood dream come true.
...a sweet stop
in the Victorian Village...
This is like
"Cinnamon Rolls Gone Wild."
[ Chuckles ]
DVD box set.
...and even a hands-on chance
to make cheese like a local.
Little Miss Muffet
was eating this
and she was
scared of a spider?
From my hometown to yours...
Is there anything
about that that doesn't
sound fantastic?
...it's the place
who made me who I am.
Like our motto is,
"Come and visit,
just don't move here."
[ Laughter ]
This is a special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
Welcome to a special edition of
[ Cow moos ]
I know --
This doesn't look like
a diner, a drive-in, or a dive.
Nope. That happens to be
the house that I grew up in.
Yes, we're in
my favorite town in the world --
Ferndale, California.
Now, this is where I grew up.
And I thought
I'd take you for a little tour,
show you some of
the inside track to Ferndale,
one of the first restaurants
I ever cooked in,
and, of course,
some of the greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
Where's Ferndale?
Well, you drive about four hours
north of San Francisco
to Humboldt County,
look for a big bridge,
and the little Victorian Village
with a population
of a whopping 1,300 or so.
That's right -- I was raised
in a Victorian Village
in a dairy town.
Makes perfect sense.
My parents, Jim and Penny,
moved here in 1970.
I was just 2 years old,
and this was my playground --
the fields, the redwoods,
the ocean.
Kind of the perfect place
for a kid
to get into a little --
well, maybe a lot -- of trouble.
So, to kick things off,
here we are --
rush hour, Ferndale, downtown.
[ Insects chirping ]
Now, this place is the first
kitchen that I ever worked at.
Since then, it's been rebuilt,
refurbished, and revitalized.
You want to talk about a
hometown-hero joint, this is it.
Welcome to the Ivanhoe.
DAVE:
New York, medium rare, up.
You can count on it being good.
Scampi.
The food is just spectacular.
DAVE: Prime rib, medium rare,
with baker.
Oh, the Ivanhoe
plays a big part in the town.
FIERI:
And it has since the '70s --
that is, the 1870s.
It's been everything
from a stagecoach stop
to a Mexican joint,
where I got
my first kitchen job.
Right here is where I realized,
at a very young age,
how bad I wanted to be
on the other side of the program
and not be a dishwasher.
It was scraping cheese
off of these enchilada platters
with a putty knife.
I told my dad,
"I hate being a dishwasher."
And he says, "Exactly."
He says, "Every chance you get,
you get on that line,
you see how they're cooking,
and one day, they'll need you."
And, no kidding,
about four weeks later,
one of the line cooks
didn't show up,
and I ran up on the line
and got to cook.
And that was my
first experience --
in this kitchen.
I am just so tripping out.
This was the kitchen line
that I cooked on.
It was called Romans Restaurant.
Stayed that way till 1997,
when local boy Dave Mogni
and his wife, Barb,
gave up on Silicon Valley
and moved back to Ferndale.
No place like home
to get our new business started.
What do you think
of this place?
Primo.
Food is dynamite.
It's just like being in
grandma and grandpa's kitchen.
FIERI: Makes sense,
since a lot of the menu
came from Dave's dad, Lino,
who owned the gas station
across the street
and used to fix my bike tires
for free.
The dude
that helped me out with
everything that had a motor
that I owned --
this is Lino, Dave's dad.
Your dad was a big influence
on the menu.
Yes.
He's full-blooded Italian,
so it's kind of
a blend
of American-Italian cuisine.
Chicken cacciatore.
It's really a special treat.
Is this the cacciatore
we're getting into?
This is
the chicken cacciatore.
Okay.
You just start with oil.
Onions.
[ Sizzling ]
Garlic.
All right, chicken broth.
Then we start adding
good old tomato paste.
Water.
Just keeps cooking down.
Keep cooking in, yep.
Then we add tomatoes...
salt...
...parsley,
fresh basil...
[ Whistles ]
Little brown sugar.
...little brown sugar...
...and red-pepper flakes.
By touch, by feel,
and my last one's a
pow right there.
You stir that in,
and that's it.
Chicken.
Braising the chicken.
Oil.
[ Sizzling ]
We use brown meat only
in this dish.
And this is where
we overseason the chicken,
because we're gonna
lose a lot of it in the pan.
So, brown it off,
both sides.
A layer of red sauce.
Another layer of chicken.
Fresh mushrooms.
In the oven --
350 for how long?
2 1/2.
2 1/2 hours?
Yep.
And then we're gonna
serve that over polenta.
Yep.
So, nice, steaming-hot
polenta here.
All right, chicken.
At least that's not like
9,000 degrees.
Where are you gonna go
with that?
Right here.
We had her dialed.
And you get
an extra thigh with it.
That's it. Yep.
Mmm.
And mix this up.
The sauce cooking down
for a couple hours.
A little Parmesan
for garnish,
parsley for color.
If that isn't old-school
Italian, I don't know what is.
Just look at that chicken.
Mmm!
I tell you, that is about
one of the most comforting
things you can eat.
Yep.
It's exactly
what I wanted it to be.
You said you would do
an old-school Italian
chicken cacciatore.
This is
what it should taste like.
Tender chicken,
creamy polenta.
A little texture
to that polenta
still not cooked
all the way out.
Everything
done the right way.
Excellent dish.
Just excellent.
And your pops
deserves mad props.
Mmm!
Chicken cacciatore up.
There's nothing like it
in this county.
Really tender,
really good sauce.
Pretty much just like mom made,
but even better.
Sorry, mom.
It's being
in this environment,
sitting in the old Ivanhoe,
and the way you decorated it.
You guys really put the
nostalgia back into the place.
One of the most moving things
that we went through --
the community showed up.
People would show up --
a husband and wife
with a bucket of tools --
and say, "What do you
want us to do today?"
I think my uncle Dane --
Dane Cowan --
did some work for you.
Oh, yeah.
They put our windows in.
Yep. Saw a bunch
of pictures of that.
Everybody was glad to hear
that the Ivanhoe was back open.
Four minutes
on the sausage and risotto.
You taught
half of these meals to Dave.
Out of everything
he has on the menu,
what's your favorite?
I like the risotto.
Risotto, Italian sausage, up.
WOMAN: The Ferndale meat market
makes the sausage,
so it's locally made.
It has really good flavor.
All right, brother,
hit it.
So, we're gonna
drop some sausage in
right in the water there.
We use olive oil and butter
to start.
Okay.
Flavor and browning.
Add garlic.
Garlic in, okay.
I like to open the garlic up
a little bit.
Arborio rice.
Yep.
So, you just
get that toasted brown.
Our chicken stock.
Then we just keep adding slowly
and letting it cook down.
This will take
about 25 minutes
to get this risotto cooked
all the way through.
The point
of adding saffron.
A lot of saffron, buddy.
It's a natural resource
here in Humboldt.
Then we just let that blend in,
and the rice will finish off.
All right, last step --
nice Parmesan cheese.
Good-looking risotto, man.
Yeah.
You can't be cheap
on the saffron.
Hey!
Italian sausage.
Perfect.
At least it's not hot.
Yeah.
Parmesan cheese
and fresh parsley.
Risotto Milanese
with homemade Italian sausage.
And that's what you call it
right here.
Mmm!
I'm very picky
about risotto.
The grains
of the Arborio rice
are very tender
but firm, not mushy.
A lot of saffron.
Mmm!
So,
the Italian sausage...
That sausage
is off the hook.
Got a little funkiness
to it.
I mean, good funkiness,
like nutmeg
or allspiceish-type flavors
to it.
That's killer.
I can't shovel it in my mouth
fast enough.
You know, they might have
the Grammys,
but in Flavortown, you'd win
an award at the Poundys.
That's good stuff, man.
Nice job.
Thanks, Guy.
Risotto and sausage.
Thank you.
It's excellent.
The sausage is flavorful,
not too spicy.
They bring the crowd in because
they've got quality food.
This is like
real-deal homemade.
The food's where it's at.
FIERI: People want to
come here just because of
how great the town is
and how cool the locals are.
I think that
the Ivanhoe reopening
just adds another
element that makes this
such a great place.
And like our motto is,
"Come and visit,
just don't move here."
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Up next...
I used to work here
after school.
...a down-home family butcher
serving up the serious
Italian sausage with a twist.
How would that look
hanging from the rear-view
mirror of the '68?
Oh, that Italian sausage
was the bomb!
I got to stop by
Ferndale Meat Company
and get some.
You guys ready
for a little road trip?
That Ferndale commute
can be a tough one.
This is
the Ferndale Meat Company.
When I was in fifth grade, going
to Ferndale Elementary School,
I used to work here
after school.
I did it all -- clean-up,
I made sandwiches,
I made jerky,
I worked in the freezer.
You are gonna love this place.
It's a local butcher shop.
You don't see
many of those anymore.
This is kind of
what you expect when
you come down here?
Yeah. Just family service,
close.
Absolutely wonderful.
All right, so,
you come back to your hometown
and you run into
your hometown buddy.
This is my buddy
Danny Sisemore.
How many times
do you think
did we eat
at the Ferndale Meat Company?
Oh, I can remember
the bell ringing for lunch,
and everybody
would almost race down here.
FIERI: And folks are still
racing down here to get some.
Curt does
a heck of a good job here.
FIERI: That's Curt Terribilini,
who bought the joint
with his sister, Pixie,
back in 2001.
All right, now,
when I was a kid,
this was the smokehouse
that I used to
load the beef jerky into.
Have you ever used this?
I wouldn't know
how to use it.
No!
No, I've never used it.
I mean, look at this thing.
[ Sighs ]
I can't believe
you don't use it.
I want to take it
and put it in my backyard.
It's yours.
"You can have it."
I knew he was gonna
say that.
[ Both laugh ]
Is this being aged
right now?
Yeah.
How long
will you dry-age this?
For about two weeks.
Then you'll bring it out here
and then break it into
whatever format they want it,
correct?
Exactly.
Total old school.
And that goes for
their Italian sausage
recipes, as well.
His Italian sausage
is second to none.
All right,
give us a rundown, man.
Grab a piece of meat.
This is what they call
special trim.
Special trim.
Yeah, it's just off the ribs.
It's a tough cut of meat,
and so
that's why we use it
for sausage,
'cause you grind it up
and cook it.
These are pork butts.
We don't
trim any fat off them.
We just chop them up.
Here you go.
And he just cuts through that
like butter.
25 pounds of beef,
25 of pork.
Okay, and the recipe from this
comes from where?
It's a family recipe.
Like, you ripped it off
from your grandmother, or...
No, she gave it to me.
She gave it to you, my --
Come on, Curt.
[ Laughs ]
Where's your grandma from?
She's from Italy,
next to the Swiss border.
Northern Italian.
This is different
than what you would think.
Like, "Oh, Italian sausage --
I get it."
This goes beyond that.
Let me tell you guys
just how much fun it is
cleaning out the grinder.
Not really that much fun.
I hate
cleaning the grinder.
I don't have to
clean the grinder, do I?
You're gonna have to
clean something.
Gah!
[ Laughs ]
Look at that.
And next,
the spice blend.
Salt.
And then we got sugar.
Grandmother's recipe.
I love this.
Pepper.
Allspice.
[ Whistles ]
Nutmeg.
And cloves.
Garlic and Burgundy wine.
Oh!
Just pour it in,
let the machine do the work.
You can smell
that red wine.
You can smell the garlic.
Oh!
Pretty good, huh?
Pretty good.
Next step is what?
We stuff it in beef casings.
FIERI: So, this is
a water-pressurized
sausage-stuffing machine?
Exactly.
That is awesome!
The casings.
Are you gonna stuff
or do you want me to stuff?
Considering that
I've never used
the water-pressurized --
Mm! I love a little bit
of intestine water on me.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
Running the throttle with
your thumb there a little bit.
Yep. You just kind of want to
get a little squeeze on it.
Then we just go like this.
There you go.
Just do this.
[ Whistling ]
Have you ever
tied sausage before?
I have tied sausage.
But I don't have
that little setup there.
Ohh.
That's awesome.
I've done it
a couple times.
No, no. It doesn't show.
And that's so
you can hang it?
How would that look
hanging from the rear-view
mirror of the '68?
Some bling.
So, I know that you guys
don't cook and sell these here,
but you got
a barbecue or something?
We got to
taste one of these.
I think they're cooking some
across the street.
Right at Humboldt Sweets.
But that's
how we do it in Ferndale --
Everybody's
helping each other out.
That's a joint
we got to check out later.
You gonna skin it?
This thing
just peels right off.
Right off the bat,
you can smell that allspice,
little bit of that clove,
the wine, and the garlic.
It's a little bit
different
than eating it over there
at the Ivanhoe.
And you say in applesauce?
Applesauce.
I think when people think
about Italian sausage,
they don't think about
eating it with applesauce,
but that is killer.
Pretty good, huh?
Add some mashed potatoes
to that, and you got a meal.
It's different
than regular Italian sausage.
I mean, this is
nutmeg and allspice.
Oh, that's good.
Not too shabby, is it?
Nice job. Thank you.
It's outstanding.
It's really good sausage.
And we appreciate him making it.
And I'm glad that he's here.
FIERI: Up next...
Hi. What would you like?
...I'm going back to the gig
that got it all going.
Thank you.
34 years later,
the pretzel cart
now comes back to Ferndale.
Can you make change
for $100?
No.
Oh, okay,
well, then keep the change.
[ Laughter ]
All right, so, here I am,
downtown Ferndale, California --
population 1,400 or so.
Now, I used to ride my bike
up and down these streets.
My parents
had a couple businesses here --
the Abraxas and what was called
Dave's Saddlery.
And I set up
my first business here.
Now, let's see.
First one was paper-bag puppets.
Then I had the Kool-Aid stand.
But I was most well-known
for the awesome pretzel cart.
Five years ago,
my foundation, CWK,
donated an Awesome Pretzel Cart
to the Ferndale
Elementary School eighth grade.
Let's see how they're doing.
Hi. What would you like?
Can I get a cinnamon-and-sugar
pretzel, please?
This is how I got my start.
At 12 years old, my dad, Jim,
helped me build
my first pretzel cart.
Heck, it only took us
six months.
It took me a lot longer to
get these kind of lines, though.
Here you go.
WOMAN: It has meant a lot
to our eighth graders.
These kids
are becoming career-ready,
learning how things work.
They've learned
salesmanship skills, marketing,
and how to
interact with the public.
Thank you.
FIERI: And it comes complete
with some sweet dividends.
GIRL:
The pretzel cart helps us raise
money for the eighth-grade trip,
and we go to Sacramento
and San Francisco.
Thank you.
Do they give you good tips?
Mm-hmm.
See, if you tell them
what you're doing --
If you say, "We're the
Ferndale Elementary
eighth grade class.
"We're raising money
for our eighth-grade trip.
"So, the pretzel's
only $4.
Tipping 10 bucks
is fine."
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: That was my approach.
Some things have definitely
not changed since I was a kid.
This woman right here
was my eighth-grade teacher.
Now,
before I say anything,
you cannot ask her
questions about me, what I
was like when I was a kid,
'cause she's just gonna
tell you I was awesome.
This is Fran Moriarty.
Absolutely, absolutely.
This is a very influential
person in my life.
When I started the pretzel cart,
I was in sixth grade,
and by the time
I got to eighth grade,
I was in full force
of Awesome Pretzel Cartness.
Now, Miss Moriarty --
she inspires me
to do a report
on the history of the pretzel.
So, we do National History Day,
and I win.
And you get to go to state.
State competition turned into
I just automatically won.
So they
sent me to nationals.
34 years later,
the pretzel cart
now comes back to Ferndale.
What do you think of this?
Well, I mean,
the life experiences
that they're getting,
the math skills
the communication skills
that they're getting --
It's amazing.
It's just amazing.
This is the first one
of many carts
that my Cooking With Kids
Foundation has donated
to youth organizations
across the country.
And these young
Ferndale Elementary students
are making us proud.
Hi. What would you like?
Cinnamon and sugar, please.
The pretzels are delicious --
I think probably some of
the best that I've had.
Thank you very much.
I would like a little bit
of salt and some cheese.
Okay.
Okay, I like it.
Nice and steamed.
Hot.
And here's the cheese.
Is it good?
It's outstanding.
$4, please.
[ Laughter ]
You never know
what it's gonna spark.
WOMAN:
They've also learned from Guy
that anybody from any small town
can do great things.
Can you make change
for $100?
Yeah.
[ Record scratches ]
Can you make change
for $100?
No.
Oh, okay,
well, then keep the change.
[ Laughter ]
Mallory, good job.
You guys are doing awesome.
FIERI: Coming up...
Oh!
This is the best apple
I've ever had.
...we're headed to
an old-time orchard...
Can you teach me
the art of the cider-making?
...for some of my favorite
real-deal apple cider.
There is nowhere safe!
I got apple juice
all over me!
FIERI: Four hours
north of San Francisco
is a place called Ferndale,
and that's where I grew up.
Check it out --
A Victorian Village
tucked away in Humboldt County
full of farms, fields,
and some of the best people
you'll ever meet.
My parents were looking for
a place to raise their kids,
and I couldn't have asked
for a better one.
And when I come back, I'm
still finding new things to do.
So, I'm not technically
in Ferndale.
Now I'm across the Eel River
about 5 miles
in a little town called Fortuna.
And I'm bringing you here
for a reason.
Now, I don't say this
very often,
but this place makes the best --
yep, you heard it
on "Triple D" --
the best apple cider.
This is Clendenen's.
The quality of their product
is amazing.
Oh, their apples are just
always so fresh and huge.
It puts a lot of smiles
on our faces.
FIERI: And around these parts,
I'm telling you --
everyone knows Clendenen's.
It's part of the community.
WOMAN:
They're kind, they're welcoming,
and you feel like
you're a part of their family
when you come in.
I think that's what
Clendenen's is all about.
FIERI:
'Cause Clif Clendenen's family
has been growing apples
in Fortuna
for more than a century.
CLIF:
My grandfather, E.C. Clendenen,
bought this place in 1908.
And I learned a lot
from my dad, Andy,
who ran this place
from the '40s through the '70s.
FIERI: And now Drew
brings the tradition
to a fourth generation.
When I was like 2 years old,
I was in a backpack
with a pair of pruning shears,
helping my dad.
So, give me the rundown.
I know it's old.
How old is it?
Okay, this orchard
was planted in 1869.
So some of these trees
date --
Like this one right back here.
This is a Minkler.
This dates from 1869.
But we've
replanted a lot of trees
and we've got a lot of
other varieties going here now.
FIERI:
That's an understatement.
Each fall, they pump out
30 different kinds of apples
from their 700 trees.
So, how do you tell
when you're ready?
CLIF: Well, they'll start to
get a little shine.
But always
the most important thing --
when the background color
starts to just
get a little bit
of yellow.
Is that ripe or not?
Yeah. Yeah.
And you got the stem
on the apple, too,
so that's good.
That's what you want?
Yeah.
So, each --
Wait, wait, wait.
This is
how you guys do this?
You come out
with this big --
Yeah.
No.
Oh, no.
This big courier bag
of apples?
Yeah.
I should probably check this
and make sure it's okay.
How many do you eat
when you're picking?
Oh, I usually
have a couple a day.
Really?
Yeah.
You guys look
pretty lean and mean.
Doesn't look like
you've been picking
bacon or anything.
[ Laughs ]
That is a Spitzenburg.
That was Thomas Jefferson's
favorite apple.
Oh!
This is the best apple
I've ever had in my life.
It's as crunchy
as a carrot.
All right, I think
the only thing I got
to do now is say,
will you teach me
the art of the cider-making?
All right.
Yeah.
FIERI: And while they
import about 25 tons of
apples for their cider,
they're growing the other
70 tons they need right here.
CLIF:
We call this fresh apple cider.
It's unpasteurized
and it's pressed fresh,
chilled down,
and immediately sold.
Let's get this straight.
The press is how old?
It's a 1916.
So, this is really
a hodgepodge of everything?
Yeah.
A mix of tart, older varieties,
like the Smith cider,
and then a good mix of,
like, sweeter varieties,
like Fujis
and blushing goldens,
and, like Mutsus.
You can tell
just by looking at each one
what they are?
Yeah.
How many gallons of juice
will this make?
That's maybe
20 or 30 gallons.
Something like that,
I'd say.
All right, so,
can you just walk me
through the process?
So, yeah,
apples get dumped in here,
just out of the box,
washed off.
They go get a little
extra wash in the water here.
So, the apples
go in here.
They'll just bunch up
as much and fall back?
There's someone here
who's kind of, you know,
assisting so that --
I know. So not too
many people are in the
tunnel at one time?
Exactly. Yeah.
So, it goes up.
This hammer mill
grinds it all up.
That just
pulverizes the apple.
Yeah, it pulverizes them.
And then this green
hopper -- this fills
up with the pulp.
There's a little trapdoor
under here.
So, you're gonna
pull the pulp door.
Yep.
And we have these cloths.
This is a press cloth.
We got this trolley,
essentially, that
moves on the track.
We have our cloth
that lays in there.
And, yeah,
this fills up with pulp.
You pull this trapdoor.
Pulp goes right into there.
And then you fold this up --
Over itself?
Yeah, you fold it up
into one unit, just like that.
You put a divider on it.
Lay that back on it.
Do the whole cloth again.
How many people?
Two.
You two?
Yeah.
Oh, this I got to see.
CLIF: Ready to hit it?
FIERI: Okay. Here we go!
Ohh!
Get out of here.
It's like we're
sending apples into
a big wood chipper.
FIERI: There are particles
of apple-ness
spraying everywhere.
There is nowhere safe.
I got apple juice
all over me!
Let me just clean you up here
a second.
But look at this natural
just juice.
Ahh!
It's like
nectar from the gods!
DREW: All right, well,
shall we squeeze this
cheese, as they say?
All right,
we're ready to juice.
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
Yeah.
See, I am
such a fan of this joint.
This is like getting milk
right from the udder.
Awesome.
Getting it
right off the tap --
okay? --
it tastes exactly the same
as when I buy it
out of the cooler.
That's right.
That's amazing.
FIERI: So, now...
So, yeah.
And there's
nothing we can do with this?
This just makes compost?
Yeah.
Couldn't we
sell this to somebody to make,
like, apple snacks
or something?
Yeah, I think, you know,
people have made horse treats
out of it,
that sort of thing.
You know, it's food grade,
so, you know,
I always let
the kindergarten kids
that come tour
eat some.
Kind of dry, but...
You got to be able to
make something out of this.
They have the best apple cider
that I've ever had.
They're top of the line.
No wonder you guys
have been in business
and are
so highly regarded
in Humboldt County --
now
all over the country.
But this is --
I am blown away, guys.
What a visit.
I mean, this is like
a childhood dream come true.
Great.
Thanks for coming.
Awesome.
FIERI: Coming up...
Yeah, you want to swim?
In this town, you got to
get geared up
and pumped up...
I'm hitting chunks!
...if you're gonna
make cheese like a local.
Are you sure
that ring is in here?
[ Cow moos ]
So, since I'm
on this side of the Eel River,
I figured I'd cruise up
Highway 101 a few miles
to check out a joint
where they're handcrafting
and hand-making
their own cheese.
You got to check it out.
This is Loleta Cheese Factory.
The cheese is delicious.
Mmm! Creamy.
I like the taste.
Real nice.
WOMAN: Every time we're in town,
we stop by here
and get some cheese to take
home.
Mmm!
WOMAN: I've been to
a lot of cheese factories,
and the quality is great.
FIERI: All from self-taught
cheese-maker Bob Laffranchi.
I was a teacher
at Eureka High School
and I was teaching agriculture
there, and one day,
one of my students
came in and said, "How
do you make cheese?"
I said, "I don't know."
I said, "Here's $15.
Go to the bookstore, get a book,
and we'll make some."
While that first batch
stunk worse than Limburger,
Bob was hooked
on the cheese-making process.
So in 1982,
he started this place,
which has grown
into a 5,000-pound-a-day
cheese-making machine.
I refer to my cheeses
as being fun cheeses
because they got
all these flavors.
They're not boring.
And you want to talk
farm to table,
it all starts with milk
from his own dairies
as close as a mile away.
Okay, let's try this.
When we talk about
farm to table,
only way you could
have this any closer
is if you had the dairy
on top of the building.
Just about, yes.
[ Laughter ]
Yeah, you want to swim?
Walk me through the stages
that it takes to get to this.
Okay,
it's gonna come in to us
and it's going to be
tested for antibiotics.
This milk came in
yesterday afternoon.
Then it's going to be
pasteurized.
Heated up to...
Heated up to 164.
Okay.
When the bacteria's
been added,
that's what's gonna
give us our flavor.
And then
the enzyme has been added.
What cheese
is this gonna make?
Jack cheese.
This is the magical part
of the cheese.
This is where we go
from liquid to solid.
Put your finger in
like this.
Uh-huh.
The enzyme
is what makes it
turn from a liquid
to a solid.
And just lift up.
And see how it breaks?
Yeah.
It's ready
to cut into curd.
We're gonna cut this curd
into little cubes,
about 3/8 of an inch
square.
We're gonna pull it
from this end.
We're just gonna
slide it down in.
Got it.
And then you
put your arm underneath,
like this,
and grasp over there.
Okay.
And then we just turn,
and you and I are gonna
walk to the other end.
And right now,
we're cutting it?
Yes.
Yours is horizontal,
and mine's vertical.
I'm hitting chunks!
Then we're gonna
go like this.
We're gonna
take your side here.
Like ships in the night.
Then we're gonna
come together.
Now we're just gonna
turn and go back
down the other --
Now, we got to
keep it on the bottom.
Yep.
Stay in track with you.
Pull it out.
Okay.
Okay, and what we're
gonna do now...
is we're gonna
do a crosscut.
And why doing it
with this process versus just
sending in, like, some
gigantic immersion blender?
This curd is very fragile,
and the corners
would fracture off.
Oh.
We'd lose
a whole bunch of cheese.
Really?
Yep.
I feel like
I'm looking for my watch
in a big thing
of oatmeal.
We make a good team,
you know that?
We're doing good.
You can see here.
See how that's already
separated?
Yeah.
That's the whey.
And so,
Little Miss Muffet --
what she would have been
looking at...
Is a bowl of this?
Let me ask you this --
Little Miss Muffet
was sitting there
eating this,
and she was
scared of a spider?
[ Laughs ]
Okay, so,
what happens now?
We're gonna
put the agitators in.
Whoa!
Whoa.
This is gonna be cool.
And we're gonna
gently start to roll this
so it doesn't
stick back together.
Now, what happens
after that?
We're gonna
drain it down halfway.
About 12.5%
of this total volume
is gonna end up
as cheese.
Wait, wait, wait.
12.5%
of everything we see here
will turn into cheese?
And the rest of it
goes out
to feed the cows.
No.
Yeah.
And then we're going to
put a filter on
and we're gonna
put cold water back
cool the curd down
to about 84 degrees.
And, at that point,
the cold water's
gonna be reabsorbed
into the curd,
and that's how we get
the additional yield.
Then they're gonna go
another 15, 20 minutes.
And then they're going to
drain all of the liquid off.
And when they got the curd
down on the bottom of the vat,
they're gonna go ahead
and they will add salt.
And then the cheese curds
are put into these boxes.
And they'll be pressed
overnight
into the 40-pound blocks.
And in the morning,
they're gonna unwrap it.
And they're gonna put it
in a vacuum-packed bag.
And then they're gonna
put it in a box.
And the result of all this
is some outrageous
Jack cheese --
or, in this case,
a big hunk of habanero Jack.
Why are you giving me
the corner off of this one?
'Cause there's more peppers
in that one.
In the corner?
[ Whistles ]
That's hot.
When I think of
a hot cheese,
this is
what I'm expecting.
It's just got
nice, warm heat,
creaminess of the cheese.
Mmm!
It's killer.
WOMAN: I like knowing
the cheese is made right here.
I've tried every flavor,
and they're all delicious.
Little, tiny place.
Artisan cheese.
There's just this whole
energy and attitude about
what you're doing.
And the cheese is the bomb.
Awesome.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
I picked up the fork again.
I'm right back in.
...a new face on Main Street...
You're like a Keebler Elf
over here.
You just
keep cranking out the food.
...going large and in charge
with the sweet stuff.
Look at the size of those.
The bigger, the better.
So, this is
the main drag of Ferndale.
I mean, that is literally it.
You see
all these Victorian storefronts.
Now, this area right here --
This is where they filmed
the movie "Outbreak,"
so the entire town of Ferndale
got used in this fantastic movie
with Dustin Hoffman.
But that's what you see.
There's no stoplights.
There's sometimes
one cop car cruising around.
And every single one
of these buildings has a story.
So, there are all these
great places and joints
you got to visit in Ferndale,
but I only got so much time.
Before I go, though,
we got to check out
kind of, like,
the new kids on the block.
These folks are making something
you don't always see
on "Triple D".
That's right --
desserts and pastries.
Well, and a whole lot more.
This is Humboldt Sweets.
WOMAN: Here's
your peppermint bark.
I'm in here at least
three to four times a week.
It's a really special place.
FIERI:
That's mom and pop to the core.
Since 2012, chef Tammy Pichulo,
husband Tony,
and their five kids
have been cranking out
a full menu of savory...
Grilled cheese
is right behind it.
...and, of course, sweet.
Oh, yeah!
TAMMY: Order up --
caramel pecan cinnamon roll.
The caramel pecan
cinnamon roll -- I love it.
I've finished it one time,
but, mostly, I share it.
[ Laughs ]
TAMMY: We're making
caramel pecan cinnamon rolls.
We've got a wild mix
of ingredients.
Yep.
We're gonna start with
the yeast.
A little bit
of the sugar in.
Warm water.
Stir that a little bit.
Warm milk.
And now
I'm gonna add the sugar.
Salt.
Got it.
Stir that a little bit.
And then I'm gonna
add my eggs to that.
Then I'm gonna add this
to our yeast mixture.
Half of the flour
to that.
All-purpose?
Yep.
Now, how many cinnamon rolls
is this gonna make us?
This is gonna make
a couple dozen.
Giant ones?
Yep.
Add melted butter.
And mix it up pretty good.
And then we're gonna add
the rest of our flour.
Is the purpose of
adding the flour in
two different stages
just because it would
be just too much to
be mixing around
trying to incorporate
that wet ingredient?
Yeah.
You'd just be
fighting it for a while?
[ Laughs ] Yeah.
Now, are we gonna let this rest
before we roll it out?
We're gonna
dump it onto our surface
and we're gonna knead it
for about eight minutes.
Let's talk about
the caramel sauce.
All right, first,
we're gonna add the butter.
Gonna let that melt
just for a minute.
Then I'm gonna
add my brown sugar to that.
Now we're gonna add
our corn syrup to this.
There you go.
And then
we'll add our cream.
Okay,
we'll spread that around
and we'll
crush the pecans up.
That's a lot of nuts.
Yeah,
it's quite a bit of nuts.
Now we're gonna mix the
brown sugar and the cinnamon.
You buy the brown sugar
by the tanker truck?
And where's this gonna go?
This is gonna go
on the cinnamon-roll dough
when I get it rolled out.
FIERI:
The dough gets rolled out...
coated with butter...
and covered
with cinnamon and brown sugar.
Then it's rolled back up,
sliced thick,
and dropped
on top of caramel and pecans.
Okay, now we're gonna let this
rise for about 45 minutes
and then we're gonna bake them
in a 350-degrees oven
for about 25 minutes.
Holy!
[ Laughs ]
Come down
and feed your family of 10.
Get out.
[ Laughs ]
This is like
"Cinnamon Rolls Gone Wild."
[ Laughs ]
DVD box set.
Gooey, tender,
nutty...
cinnamonamony.
It's outrageous.
It's excellent.
It's killer. I--
I'm picking up the fork again.
I'm right back in.
[ Laughs ]
Great job.
All right. Thank you.
[ Laughs ]
Caramel pecan roll.
They're ridiculously good.
So, I tell you all the time
on "Triple D"
that I wish that Hunter or Ryder
or Jules could try this,
and, eh, well,
they're not always there.
So, here I am
up in Ferndale,
and the kids are back
in Santa Rosa in the school.
So, I got my fill-in kid.
This is kind of like my nephew.
This is Jesse Barrer.
Now, Jesse, you've had
everything on their menu
six times or more.
What's the best part
about the cinnamon roll?
How big it is.
I think it's bomb.
"Bomb" is good.
You have to share it.
FIERI:
Because here, I'm told
you got to save room
for the scones.
Ham-and-cheddar scone
with gravy.
Every town has someone who's,
like, the godfather of food.
Now, for me as a little kid
growing up in Ferndale,
this was the guy.
This is Curley Tate.
Now, I've known Curley --
Or I should say
Curley's known me
since I was that big.
And I don't want to
hear any of the stories.
[ Laughs ]
I got one.
Don't!
You know great food.
You've done food
all over the country.
Humboldt Sweets
is kind of a funky little joint,
but their food
and their style --
what do you think?
Incredible.
You know,
it's like coming home.
This thing is savory.
Ham, cheese, onion,
bacon gravy.
How can you go wrong?
FIERI:
Now what are we into?
We're gonna do our
ham-and-cheddar scone
with green onions.
So, I'm gonna
put our flour in first.
Sugar.
Baking powder.
And a little bit of salt.
Then I'm gonna
add my butter to that.
Cold? Cut it in?
Yep.
Gonna add our ham
to that.
Really? We're getting into it
right now, huh?
Yeah.
Green onions.
Sharp cheddar.
We're gonna add the cream.
There's more ingredients
than there is flour in this.
[ Laughs ]
It'll barely hold together.
Heavy cream?
Yep, heavy cream.
You're like a Keebler Elf
over here.
You just
keep cranking out the food.
Just keep going, mixing,
moving, shaking,
laughing.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
Then I'm gonna start
making our balls.
You don't want to form them
too firm, do you?
Nope.
Just enough
to hold them together.
Yep.
Look at the size of those.
[ Laughs ]
The bigger, the better.
What temperature
will these bake at?
These are gonna bake
at 400 degrees
for about 28 minutes.
28 minutes?
Yep.
Next up,
what are we making?
Bacon gravy
for our ham-and-cheddar scone.
Is there anything
about that that doesn't
sound fantastic?
I'm gonna brown my bacon.
[ Sizzling ]
Okay, so,
we brown down the bacon.
Then we'll add in
the flour, make the roux.
That'll be the beginning
of the gravy.
Yep.
Stir this till it's brown.
Throw some milk
in there now.
Okay.
Fast. Fast.
Faster, faster, faster!
Faster. [ Laughs ]
So, that's gonna
tighten up.
Yep.
We're gonna add our bacon.
Little salt and pepper.
Now onto the scone.
Excellent.
That looks like
a good heaping helping of --
Look at that now, huh?
That was awesome.
[ Laughs ] Thank you.
It's great. I mean, it's what
you love about a scone.
Nice and light,
but then super-savory
with the ham and the cheese
and the onions.
That's ridiculous.
I love the smell.
It is amazing.
Every time you come here,
you try something new,
and it's your new favorite.
This is
what Ferndale's all about --
scratch-made, homemade,
locally owned
and operated.
Excellent job.
[ Laughs ] Thank you.
So, that's it
for this special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
in Ferndale.
I'll see you next time
on "Triple D."
You want me to
dump it in as I go, or...
If you could get it
to come from there
into the bag
by itself magically,
I'll definitely watch.
Okay, let's watch.
'Cause you can get
right out of the meat business
if you can
make that happen.
[ Laughs ]
I'm not Uri Geller.
Dang!
'Cause if that was gonna happen,
I was in.