Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
...we're rocking
the full spectrum...
Look over there!
Pretty bird!
...from meatballs to lollipops.
Wow!
Yeah.
Hello, governor.
In Miami, Florida...
Vaca frita!
...a true veteran...
Thank you
for serving our country.
Thank you very much.
...dishing out
a Latin menu mash-up.
That is a Thanksgiving
in a burrito...
[ Chuckles ]
...just Cuban style.
In Salt Lake City, Utah...
Let me put on my muumuu.
...a snowboarder turned chef
sharing grandma's Italian...
Today we're making
mom mom's gravy.
Who?
...with a super-sized spin.
[ New Jersey accent ] Got
meatballs the size of your head.
And in Sandy, Utah...
Oh, come on now.
...a down-home joint...
The sign does not do credit to
what goes on in the crazy hut.
...putting twists
on the classics...
Are you just
making things up?
...right down to dessert.
This travels well
in that jeep,
so we'll just --
This'll be fine.
Can I get a box, please?
Of course.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here in South Miami
on Sunset Drive.
I mean, it has been years
since I was here last.
I think it was 2008.
I was at Scully's.
I mean, just a couple
hundred yards that way.
Well, I hear there's a new game
in town you got to check out,
where they're doing
burgers and tacos
like you never seen before.
This is Latin House.
Yellowtail up.
Talk about Latin fusion --
This is where it's at.
Your Madlove Burger.
Thank you.
It's a great restaurant.
FIERI: One that Cuban-born chef
Michell Sanchez
opened in 2012
after some truly
dedicated service.
I was in the air force
for four years.
Thank you
for serving our country.
Thank you very much.
And he's still serving,
this time a mix of Latin
cultures close to his heart.
Sneaky Nacho Cana Asada.
My wife is Mexican,
and so a lot of our dishes
are that Cuban heart
with the little sidekick
of Mexican flair.
The Chimi burrito,
that is my favorite.
It's kind of a mix between
a Cuban and a Mexican burrito.
We're gonna do our vaca frita
for our Chimi.
Vaca frita!
Vaca frita.
We're gonna start off
with our chopped onions.
So, we got the green peppers,
whole garlics,
and then our bay leaf.
This is USDA choice
flank steak.
Just gonna cook it down.
While that's working,
we're gonna make the mojo?
Correct.
Classic mojo marinade.
Sliced onions.
Naranja agria.
Come on.
Sour orange, baby.
Sour orange.
Chopped garlic.
A little bit of salt.
We're just gonna let this
kind of marry together.
So, this is the vaca frita.
This is the flank steak
that's cooked down.
I should probably just try this
for, like --
Yeah, just a test?
Oh!
So, what we do is
shred it by hand.
In the ropa vieja style.
Exactly, and removing
all the little connective tissue
that you have.
Whatever you say.
[ Chuckles ]
Once it's all shredded,
we'll go ahead
and take our mojo,
pour it over the top.
All right, let's do this.
[ Sizzling ]
Exact translation of
"vaca frita" -- "fried cow" --
so you got to get it
nice and crispy.
While that's going,
we'll take the tortilla,
throw it on the flattop,
give it a nice little
warm-up.
That's it?
Voilà.
All right, so we got
our three-cheese blend.
You want to start
on the base.
Chuchi rice.
Isn't that
your mom's name?
That's my mom's nickname,
is "Chuchi."
Put the sweet plantains
directly inside the burrito.
Then we take the vaca...
...and we roll,
squeeze the ends,
fold again, push in.
Always make sure you push it in,
'cause it will blow up on you
when it goes and gets dropped
for the flash fry.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're gonna fry it?
I'm gonna drop it.
Cool.
Oh, a Chimi football.
There you go.
I'm gonna slice it open.
You got all that goodness
inside.
Look at that.
The avocado lime.
The Crema Mexicana.
Sour cream.
We use these as our fries.
We call it our tangled love.
Our fresh pico de gallo.
The Chimi burrito.
Don't do
the fork-and-knife thing.
Do it the right way.
Like that.
[ Silverware clatters ]
[ Laughs ]
You get the salty meat
and this deep, rich beef flavor,
and then you get that
super-seasoned rice,
and, all of a sudden, that
fried sweet plantain comes in.
I mean, wow.
That is a Thanksgiving
in a burrito...
just Cuban style...
with Mexican influence...
[ Chuckles ]
...with French fries on top.
[ Laughs ]
Chimi burrito.
The meat is so tender
and so full of flavor.
WOMAN:
The kicker -- the maduros.
The plantains,
when you take a bite of that,
it's like it explodes
in your mouth.
I want to introduce you
to a neighbor of yours
200 yards away
over at Scully's.
This is a "Triple D" legend,
man.
So, I thought I would
bring him over here to
give you a little insight
of what happens when you get in
the "Triple D" world.
Just get prepared for it,
and just get your stamina going,
'cause it's gonna be
wall-to-wall.
You got anything else for me
in the kitchen?
Yeah, we're gonna go do
some lobster right now.
The lobster lollipops
are delicious.
The presentation is amazing.
Your lobster lollipops.
FIERI: So,
this is a spiny lobster.
This is the way we kind of
take apart the lobster.
Go.
You have all this beautiful meat
inside. Nice sharp blade.
You can kind of
just slice through.
Then put your weight
down on it.
Take your finger,
kind of fix it
right in there
between the meat and the shell.
You want to get
nice big chunks.
So, then we take our chunks,
put them in our seasoned flour.
We take off
the excess flour,
and we drop it into our tempura
and into the oil.
And we go ahead
and take the tails, fry them,
and plate them
on the presentation
and deep-fry the head,
also.
Gives it a nice, big,
bright-red color.
All right, so this is
our lobster lollipops.
It's four sticks,
two pieces per stick.
Dig it.
We'll go ahead and put the tail
on the bottom of the plate.
Our beautiful head.
Three sauces.
Mango habanero, the aioli,
and the garlic cilantro.
Very, very hot and sweet,
so I don't know if you want to
start with that one
and work your way up.
Yeah, that's gonna hurt.
It's like a good burn.
Wow!
Yeah.
Hello, governor!
Cool.
You get a little sweet kiss
on the tongue.
Refreshing.
And then it just -- aah!
Just burns out
the rest of your mouth.
And then...
Our roasted tomato
and garlic.
You really get
a different profile in each one.
They're great.
And it's super, super fresh.
Chef, you rocked the house, man.
Thank you, man.
Thank you so much.
The lobster pops are delicious.
You dip it in the signature
sauces, it's incredible.
This is Dr. Mori,
a buddy of mine.
Lives down here in Miami.
Tell me what you think
of Latin House.
Great stuff.
Fantastic.
It's a hidden gem that everybody
should experience.
Big thank you to you.
I'm glad to see that you guys
get to meet each other.
It's nice
to be back on Sunset.
Anybody moves in that I need to
come check out, you let me know.
Right on.
FIERI: Coming up...
All right, let's hit it.
...we're headed west
to Salt Lake City...
Come on down
for the Lumberjack Special.
...for a meatball-makin'
smackdown.
You know what?
I'll be here all week.
So, I'm here in Salt Lake City,
Utah, right on Main Street,
about four blocks
from the state capitol,
to check out a joint
where an east-coast transplant/
snowboarder/bartender
has opened up a joint
where he's serving
his grandma's recipes.
This is
Maxwell's East Coast Eatery.
Four-cheese ravioli
in the window.
WOMAN:
Donnie Brasco with meatballs.
Scale of 1 to 10,
I would rate this place an 11.
MAN: Caprese Salad.
It's got that home-style cooking
to it.
FIERI: Flavors Jersey-born
Steven Maxwell started serving
when he opened in 2008.
How'd you get here?
I went to Park City and planned
on bartending for a winter,
and I just never left.
That was it?
That was it.
How good is this Italian?
I don't know
what's going on here,
but it's an infusion
of good stuff that I love,
and I just want to
get more of it.
MAXWELL: Philly cheesesteak.
Lasagna.
Yo,
chicken parm in the window.
Love the chicken parm.
Big, thick pieces
of white chicken.
There's nothing like it
in the state of Utah.
FIERI:
That's because the sauce that
kicks it off is no Utah native.
What are we making?
Today we're making
mom mom's gravy.
Who?
Mom mom's --
my grandmother.
I don't see it everywhere else,
but New Jersey, see,
people call tomato sauce
on Sunday is called gravy.
All right, let's hit it.
We're gonna sauté
a little olive oil
with fresh onion,
roasted garlic.
Okay.
We're just gonna add
our San Marzano tomatoes.
Are you gonna marry these back
and forth to rinse them out?
I'll do the real deal.
There we go.
It's like the bucket brigade.
[ Chuckles ]
All the cans
are [whistles] washed out.
Some paste. Now?
Now we're gonna add
our dry ingredients.
Sugar, salt, pepper.
Dry parsley?
Dry parsley.
And a mother lode of basil.
Fresh basil.
How long
we gonna let this cook?
Six to eight hours.
And when this reduces down,
we're gonna hit it
with an immersion blender?
Exactly.
So, tell me what makes
great chicken parmesan.
We use panko breadcrumbs
instead of just regular...
Italian breadcrumbs. Okay.
It's a little bit lighter,
gonna keep the chicken
a little bit crispier.
So, this is a milanaise breast,
so you cut the breast down.
Are you pounding these first?
We are gonna pound them...
Awesome.
...lightly.
Max, you know the old concept
wet hand, dry hand?
Yes.
Avoid Frankenstein fingers.
Is that right?
Where did you get that?
That's what we call them
in my family.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
[ Groans ]
[ Laughs ]
What we'll do is we'll brown it
off both sides,
we'll put it onto a tin,
and we'll cover it with
a mozzarella/provolone mixture,
and then we'll bake it off
in the oven, melt it up.
Put a little bit
of mom mom's gravy in a pan.
Take our homemade fettuccini
down into the water,
give it a little stir
so it doesn't stick.
Okay.
Sauce is hot.
Drain our pasta.
Whoa.
Chicken parm's out.
Then we'll plate it up.
And next time
in Salt Lake City,
come on down
for the Lumberjack Special.
Dude.
You top with some cheese.
Finish with a little parsley.
There you go.
Let me put on my muumuu.
[ Chuckles ]
And this is how your
grandma would make it
when you were a kid?
This is how she'd make it.
The slow-cooked gravy,
homemade pasta,
the chicken parm,
thick breading, melted cheese,
but that's about as real deal
as you're gonna get it, man.
Nicely done. Nicely done.
Right on.
WOMAN: Chicken parmesan.
It's great food, hearty.
All the recipes basically
come from your childhood.
Yes.
Back to my grandmother's house.
So, you're back
to your grandma's house.
Her restaurant was open
in the '30s and the '40s,
but it was the front of their
house, like a lot of immigrants.
All of us,
all the kids learned
how to roll pasta,
make raviolis, gnocchi.
FIERI: And grandma's recipe
for a man-sized meatball.
Spaghetti, 10-ounce meatball.
I'm a little bit intimidated
by that meatball.
It's really big.
[ Chuckles ]
I don't know if I'm gonna
be able to eat all that.
Making a 10-ounce meatball.
A what?
10-ounce meatball.
Starts at 12, cooks down to 10.
That's how your grandmother
used to make it?
No, she made me make
the little tiny ones,
but I'd always want to
make a big one.
All right,
let's get into this.
All right.
Pepper, parsley, crushed red,
kosher salt, oregano, basil.
Finish it off
with parmesan cheese.
All the dry
comes together.
Right on.
Sitting over here, we have 80/20
ground and Italian sausage.
Right.
Okay.
Start by adding our eggs.
Drop our dries.
Worcestershire.
Little water for moisture.
Okay.
Fresh breadcrumbs.
And we're mixing this all up
like a gigantic tartar salad.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay, now how good are you
at grabbing
the 12 ounces of meat?
Takes years of practice.
I bet it does.
Hang on.
How close
do you think you are?
I'm pretty close.
Going for 12 ounces.
Where are we at? 10?
That's not 10.
You're looking down at it.
That's 12.
[ Laughs ]
That's how -- Look over there!
Pretty bird!
I got to go after that 12.
Could be a bit heavy,
but we'll see.
Camera shows it at 12.
You know what?
I'll be here all week.
Okay, so the meatballs
cook off in the oven
then get dropped
in mom mom's sauce.
We're gonna serve them today
with spaghetti.
Parmesan.
Finish with a little parsley.
[ New Jersey accent ] Yeah,
come on down to Maxwell's.
We got meatballs
the size of you're head.
It's got great flavor,
it's very rich.
Love the Italian sausage.
It's everything you want in
an old-school Italian meatball.
Max, excellent job, bro.
I always leave satisfied and
probably with a to-go box, too.
you really have brought
all the pieces and all
the components together,
and you're delivering these
folks here in Salt Lake City
a real experience.
Nicely done.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
up the road to Sandy, Utah...
There's nothing about this
I don't love.
...for killer bites...
Give me the croquettes.
...and pizza with personality.
That's a meal of a pizza.
So, I'm here on 7th East,
and I'm about 20 miles from
downtown Salt Lake City, Utah.
Now, I'm at the base
of the Wasatch Mountains,
and that's where you'll find
Alta and Snowbird,
you know,
those great ski resorts.
Now, there's a lot of reasons
to come to this area,
but I hear after you eat at this
joint, it'll be one of them.
This is Tin Roof Grill.
SEADER:
White-bean steak pizza.
It's delicious.
Garlic cheddar burger.
Everything they have here
is fantastic.
Sizzle shrimp.
And the food's legit?
Food's money.
Beyond legit.
FIERI: Something chef and owner
Mike Seader banked on
when he left his job
as a corporate food
and beverage director
in 2012.
Took a 75% cut in pay,
spent my life's savings,
and bought this restaurant.
Wow.
You made it sound so attractive.
[ Laughs ]
And the investment's paying off
thanks to Mike's
old-school approach to cooking.
Pretty much they make everything
here from scratch.
Croquettes.
[ Bell dings ]
Ham and potato
and cheese croquettes.
A fried ball of amazing.
Okay, what are we making?
We're making the brine for our
in-house smoked Canadian bacon
that's gonna be used
to make the croquettes.
I'm just gonna start off
with about a gallon of water.
Fresh sage, thyme, sugar.
Darlin'.
Pink salt.
Okay.
Fresh chopped garlic,
kosher salt.
Mix that up.
Do we submerge that
48 hours?
Just go right to the smoker.
Straight to the smoker.
Dig it.
Couple hours.
Oh, come on now.
That's legit Canadian bacon.
I mean real legit.
Just gonna dice that up.
Gonna put the croquettes
together.
Little Béchamel, cheddar cheese,
shredded potato, black pepper.
Look at that.
Canadian bacon.
There's nothing about this
I don't love.
Portion them up like so.
Okay, a little flour.
Little flour.
Buy into that.
Little seasoned egg wash.
Seasoned egg wash --
salt, pepper.
Some panko.
Panko.
All right, so we take these now,
and then we'll fry them at what?
350.
Give me the croquettes.
All right, here you go.
[ Whistles ]
What are you doing to me?
Give those a try.
Be careful,
they're heavy inside.
Look at the cheese
oozing out of that.
Mmm. Let me break it down
for you like "hammer time."
I've been around the world
from London to the bay.
[ Laughter ]
I would say that this is in
the perfect realm of croquettes.
Right amount of crust
and the right amount of Béchamel
to bind it.
Crunch, creaminess,
texture.
That's ridiculous.
Nicely done.
Croquettes.
Thank you.
It's the real deal.
I mean, it's fresh.
It's like a flavor explosion
in your mouth.
The range of food that they have
is kind of unique.
Burgers, the pastas.
WOMAN: Tapas that range
from Asian influence,
Italian influence,
American influence.
MAN: All the pizzas here
are to die for...
FIERI: With toppings
that are far from typical.
We're gonna make a marinade
for our flat-iron steaks.
These are gonna go on
a great white-bean pizza.
Back up. Wait a second.
What did you just tell me?
White-bean and steak pizza.
Are you just making things up,
making concoctions?
Start off with ginger,
green onions, soy sauce.
We're gonna add the lime juice,
crushed red pepper.
Now we're gonna marinade
our flat-iron steaks.
How long's
this gonna go on?
72 hours.
We'll make
some white-bean paste.
White beans!
Beans that have been cooked
in chicken stock,
little bit of garlic,
little lemon juice,
little roasted garlic,
olive oil, dry thyme.
Great.
Little black pepper.
And salt.
Give this a taste.
Just give me that.
Mmm! Beans are done.
Time to cook the steak.
Next up,
got our pizza dough.
What's going first?
Pesto.
White-bean puree.
Chopped tomato.
Little red onion.
Pop that into the oven.
What temp
we cooking that oven at?
425.
Halfway through.
We're gonna have the steak
that's gonna be cooked rare,
slice it.
Pop it right on there,
let it finish up in the oven.
Okay.
And what are we gonna
throw on it now?
Fresh basil.
Dude, you got it all --
a rustic pesto, the creamy
beans, great amount of steak.
The crust is dynamite.
That's a meal of a pizza.
Right on, man.
Great job.
White-bean steak pizza.
It's fantastic. The steak's
perfect, just the way I like it.
Yeah, please do.
That's what it's for.
So, we're hanging out
in Sandy, Utah, at the Tin Roof,
and when we come back, we're
gonna make the bomb cheesecakes.
I want the best one you got.
You're gonna get it.
Welcome back.
Hanging out at Tin Roof Grill
in Sandy, Utah.
And I'm gonna tell you
something, dude --
The sign does not do credit
to what goes on
in the crazy hut.
We really enjoy the cheesecake
here.
It's homemade, it's fresh.
They've got a whole board
of cheesecakes.
Show me the cheesecakes.
SEADER: First up,
we're gonna start off --
Gonna be a raspberry
Charlotte cheesecake.
And this is
the number-one seller?
Yes.
We're gonna use the pound cake
as a crust.
You're making a pound cake
to make the crust
for the cheesecake?
Absolutely.
I do it every day.
We're gonna mix up
the cheesecake.
Little sugar, little flour,
vanilla, raspberry liqueur.
Slowly add
the cream cheese,
making sure it's gonna be
nice and smooth.
We're gonna slowly add
those eggs.
All mixed up.
Now we're gonna add
some fresh raspberries.
So, slowly fold those in
so they don't break apart.
Cut our pound cake.
We're just breaking a pound cake
up and just jamming it in there.
I like the way you roll.
About half of it in there.
Because we're gonna bake
the bottom half 30, 40 minutes.
Bring it out.
Now we're gonna add
the rest of the batter.
Second time we put it in,
we put it in a water bath.
It's gonna keep our cheesecake
from being soft in the middle.
How long's it bake then?
About 45 minutes.
Then we let it cool
overnight.
Chop up some pound cake,
put it on there,
then
a white-chocolate ganache.
Top it off
with a couple of raspberries.
Now we're gonna pop a little
raspberry syrup on there.
[ Whistles ]
Little powdered sugar.
This is so rich, so creamy.
Studded with the fresh
raspberries, the ganache.
The whole thing,
it's outstanding.
When you think
righteous cheesecake, that's it.
This is one of my really close,
dear friends.
This is Spencer Leto,
and Spencer goes to school
up in Park City.
So I figured I have to ask what
he thinks of the cheesecake.
Raspberries
are good, fresh,
and the pound cake on top
just tops it off.
This travels well
in that jeep,
so we'll just --
This'll be fine.
Can I get a box, please?
Of course.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
How am I looking?
[ Laughs ]
Hmm?
Am I good?
[ Laughter ]