Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Performing nightly.
...we're hitting up
family joints...
If I do eat it all,
can I just sleep in the walk-in?
...rocking international eats.
I dig it.
In Salt Lake City, Utah...
Outrageous.
...generations of Greek...
Courageous outrageous.
...served up
with a side of Brooklyn.
Any good chef tastes first
before he lets his subjects.
Then, in nearby Holladay,
Utah...
It's an Asian Philly steak.
It is
an Asian Philly steak.
...a husband-and-wife
Vietnamese joint...
Don't "pho-get" it.
...dishing out the goodness
that just doesn't quit.
You got sweet, you got spicy,
you got salty,
you got fatty,
you got crunchy.
And on the island of Oahu...
I'm not gonna get invited
to the luau like this, am I?
...two brothers giving props
to their family
with real-deal Hawaiian.
It's like a meat waterfall
in Flavortown.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here in Salt Lake City,
Utah, in the University District
to check out a joint that --
well, let me be honest
with you --
looks a little fancy-schmancy,
you know what I'm saying?
But my rule is,
never judge a book by its cover,
'cause I hear this joint has
the off-the-hook Greek food.
This is Aristo's.
WOMAN:
Lamb shank.
I'm never disappointed
in the dish.
[ Speaking Greek ]
Real, authentic Greek food.
It's phenomenal.
And Aristo is what makes
this place.
FIERI:
But chef, owner,
and Brooklyn native
Aristo Boustikakis
was ready to quit
before he even started.
2003, I was like, "I'm done.
I want to go back to New York.
The only way I'm staying
is if I open my own place."
That's when the family back home
kicked in
to help him open the joint.
Now, 10 years later,
he's armed with Mom's recipes,
and the rest is history.
You have now brought the food
to the people.
10 years of I want to call
education -- I mean, octopus?
If I would've tried putting
octopus on 10 years ago,
we would've been shut down.
But now it's
a whole different story.
MAN: Love the octopus.
It's delicate. It finishes well.
It's amazing.
Octopus up.
It is probably one of
my favorite items on the menu.
Talk about octopus.
This batch actually came in,
believe it or not, Tunisia.
Look at that guy.
Beautiful, right?
I love octopus.
We boil these for three hours
in some salted water.
We add the red wine to the
octopus for the last 20 minutes.
Octopus is done.
Time to get these guys out.
We'll let this cool down
and make our sauce.
We start off with the prized
extra-virgin olive oil
from my village.
They've got olive trees
that are 4,600 years old.
You could drink that.
Whoa. I just did.
Wow, that's good.
And we got fresh-squeezed
lemon juice.
We got our salt, we got our
pepper, and we got our oregano.
That's it, brother.
Nice and simple.
Mmm! All right.
Let's grill some octopus.
Now it's time
to portion this guy out.
Look how tender
that is, man.
Look at that.
We got to oil up
our grill
so the tentacles don't stick,
right?
Whoo.
Performing nightly.
That's a big portion,
dude.
Go big or go home.
We hit this up
with a little oil.
You want to get that char going,
right?
You don't want to cook it
for more than like three minutes
a side.
I like the way this is going.
Gorgeous.
Take this over,
place it in our bath.
Really?
Look at this guy right here,
bro.
Look at that tentacle.
Look at what you're
about to have.
Got to get some more
of that special sauce.
All right.
That's ridiculous.
It's tender.
It still tastes like octopus.
All you did was use
awesome ingredients --
quality ingredients.
This is really outrageous.
If you don't think
you like octopus,
come down here
and try this.
I'll put that up
against anybody.
When you do, they're gonna
smell like octopus.
[ Laughter ]
Grilled octopus.
MAN: It's always tender.
It's always fresh.
It's the only thing I ever order
when I come here.
This is Viet Pham.
Viet owns two restaurants --
one here --
and he is also winner
of "Iron Chef."
What Aristo does to this,
it's super-tender.
That char sets it over the top.
It's perfect.
A cross between old-school
and modern Greek.
Absolutely.
FIERI: And it doesn't get any
more old-school
at a Greek joint than lamb.
The gyro lamb threw me off
the veggie wagon.
I became a meat eater.
FIERI: And Aristo
likes to mix it up a little.
BOUSTIKAKIS:
Lamb tacos up.
Lamb tacos at a Greek joint.
Dig it.
We use New Zealand lamb.
It's similar terrains --
rolly, grassy hills.
Rolly, grassy?
Rolly, grassy hills.
You want to get the oil
on there,
so you make sure
your spices stick.
So we go with salt, pepper,
granulated garlic.
And a little oregano.
We get a little oil
in the pan.
Fat side down.
Sear both sides.
We got our onions, right?
We got our carrots, bay leaves,
we got some water.
Help that take a bath.
That's why we got to wear
aprons, man.
I thought that was, like,
a dance dress.
Okay.
A little bit more salt.
Granulated garlic here, pepper,
and some more Greek oregano.
Cover it with some foil.
Aluminum foil.
Slap it in the oven --
375, four hours.
We making a pico that goes
with our lamb tacos, right?
I'm a freak-o for the pico.
There's our chopped tomatoes.
We got some diced cucumbers,
right?
We got our peppers,
chopped red onions, fresh mint.
In place of the cilantro.
I'm liking where this is going.
A little bit of lime juice,
a little lemon juice.
Got some pepper.
We got our salt,
granulated garlic.
Any good chef tastes first
before he lets his subjects.
Let me make sure
this is all right.
The key, really,
about that
is how fresh, crisp,
and how small it's cut.
Awesome.
Let's cook some lamb.
We had our lamb legs
that I cooked off.
We remove that au jus.
We let them cool down
a little bit.
Now we're gonna
shred them.
No oil or anything
in the pan.
You ladle some of that au jus,
and we strained it.
Look at that.
How many tortillas you want,
boss?
We're doing four tortillas.
There you go.
Let's plate it up.
Got a nice little fennel salad.
Tzatziki, right?
100% yogurt.
Smells like it's been roasted
on a spit.
Really does.
Pico.
Okay.
All right.
Then we top it off.
Feta, right?
Nice and crumbled.
There you go.
Dude, outrageous.
Courageous outrageous.
The lamb's perfect, tortillas
are great, the feta's fantastic,
the pico is outstanding
with that cucumber in there.
If I do eat it all,
can I just sleep in the walk-in?
I got a couch in the office
for you.
Heard about that couch, but I
don't want to sleep on that one.
It's just a great mix of fresh
with the lamb and the sauce.
Everything kind of just works
really well together.
This is the only place I eat
Greek food.
You can't beat it.
Man, nothing but props to you.
Congratulations.
Your mom and dad have to be
super-proud.
I don't know what happened
to him, but you got to be proud.
FIERI: Coming up, I'm bringing
some backup to Holladay, Utah...
I had to bring
the sandwich man himself in.
...for an off-the-hook
Vietnamese bahn mi...
This is one of the best hot
sandwiches I've had in my life.
...that's got me speechless.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
So I'm here in Holladay, Utah,
about 10 minutes southeast of
Salt Lake, to check out a joint
that I hear is doing
the rockin' bahn mi sandwich.
And to make sure it's rocking,
I brought this cat,
my buddy Jimmy John Liautaud
from Jimmy John's Sandwiches,
to qualify it.
This is Oh Mai.
Oh Mai.
Brisket pho ready to go.
This place is amazing.
Layers of flavor.
It's almost like traveling
to Vietnam.
WOMAN: The food at this place
is just as good as the people
that own this place.
FIERI:
That would be a Vietnamese-born
husband-and-wife team of Long
and Anna Tram,
two veterans of
the Salt Lake restaurant scene
looking to switch it up a bit.
We finally decided to retire,
so that's why we bought
this little space.
You retired and did this?
[ Laughing ] Yes.
FIERI:
I guess retirement means
serving up
righteous family recipes.
Everything here is fantastic.
FIERI: Since I got my boy
Jimmy John rolling with me,
you know I got to start off
with a standout sandwich.
Bahn mi.
The sandwich is just amazing.
FIERI: Let's talk about
what we're gonna make.
We're gonna make
the pickled carrots and daikon.
That go on the sandwich
to give it all the crunch?
Everything sound good with you
so far?
Sounds good.
Wow. What a machine.
Okay.
Now we're ready?
Carrots.
Daikon.
And you want them longways?
Yeah, long way, please.
Fire it up.
So now we have to
marinate them.
First vinegar, sugar.
And...
...water.
How long will it take
until these pickle?
About two days.
This is the rib eye that goes
to the sandwich.
Correct.
And then you put in the butter.
Let it melt a little bit.
And then onions
and garlic.
Okay.
And just sauté it
just a little bit.
And then you start adding
the rib eye.
Oh, that looks
delicious.
Now, do you do this
for every sandwich fresh?
Yes. We cook to order.
It's beautiful.
Soy sauce, sugar,
and then black pepper.
So our meat's
about medium-rare?
Medium-rare
to medium-cooked.
Now we're ready to go make
the sandwich.
So what I would do
is just cut it out.
With scissors?
Yes. [ Laughs ]
And then we
hollow this out.
Who taught you
how to do that?
Me. [ Laughs ]
It's critical.
We call it "canoeing."
Just the garlic butter
and then mayo
and then romaine lettuce
and then the rib-eye meat
and then black vinaigrette
house sauce,
black pepper,
cucumber...
[ Whistles ]
...tomato...
That looks good.
...red onion,
jalapeño pepper...
Oh, I like the jalapeño.
...carrots and daikon
and cilantro.
It's an Asian Philly steak.
It is
an Asian Philly steak.
And that's all she wrote.
Here we go.
That is unbelievable.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
[ Laughs ]
What do you get, Jimmy?
What are your flavors?
I'm getting the fresh-cooked
rib-eye steak,
the sweet vinaigrette.
I love the cilantro,
and the jalapeño kicker
is just off the chart.
You got sweet, you got spicy,
you got salty,
you got fatty,
you got crunchy.
I mean, you've got
the whole umami going on, and...
But my favorite part,
without question,
is the carrot
and the daikon.
This is one of the best hot
sandwiches I've had in my life.
It's incredible.
It's like an explosion
of flavors.
Crunchy, crusty.
Just awesome.
I know you got to bounce.
Happy skiing to you.
Thank you very much.
I had to bring
the sandwich man himself in.
Yeah.
Okay?
So nice to meet you.
What a treat this was for me.
You're the best.
Thank you, Jimmy.
Now that Jimmy rolled out,
I can get Anna's take
on one of my all-time faves
all to myself...
Here is
your brisket pho.
In my world of pho,
this is one of the best.
...when we come back.
I wish I could get in it.
FIERI: "Triple D" is parked
at Oh Mai in Holladay, Utah,
for some legit Vietnamese...
I love the food so much,
I can eat it every day.
FIERI: ...and a dish
I can never get enough of.
ANNA:
Brisket pho is ready.
Spelled P-H-O with an accent
across the top of it.
But it is pronounced "fuh."
Yes. Correct.
So don't "pho-get" it.
Don't pho-get it.
[ Laughs ]
Sorry. I had to.
This is beef bones.
Yes. Correct.
Beef bone.
We're gonna cook off
the beef bones first.
Here.
You want some help?
Yes, please.
Thank you. Strong hand.
Next, we're gonna put
the brisket into the pot.
This will cook
for about three hours.
You'll see, like, a little bit
of a foam coming to the top,
and we'll skim that off
as it goes
to get the broth
to be as clear as possible.
Yes. Correct.
While that is being cooked,
then we can start roasting
the spices.
A little cinnamon.
Star anise.
Amomum.
Amomum?
Yes.
I got to see
what this is.
It comes from
the cardamom family.
Okay. So we're gonna toast these
about five minutes.
Take out
the cooked brisket.
Now we add
the spice in?
Yes.
Look at that.
I've made some satchels before,
but that's ridiculous.
[ Whistles ]
How long are we gonna
steep that in there?
For about six more hours.
Wow.
And I'm gonna put this in
while --
While that's simmering?
Yes.
So we've got the roasted ginger
and onions.
I like this.
Crystallized rock sugar?
Yes.
Am I doing good?
You're doing perfectly.
And a little bit of salt?
And salt. Yep.
So after we get done
simmering this for six hours --
We're gonna take out the bone
and whatever's in there,
and then the broth is ready
to go.
I want to taste this.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
So now we're ready
for the noodle.
You just pour
the noodle in.
So that rice noodle went
really fast.
And then you put in the brisket.
Put in the broth.
Oh.
Then you just garnish it
with green onion, cilantro,
and red onions,
and, last but not least,
the black pepper.
Little Thai basil in mine.
See, I have my method.
I'm Thai basil, jalapeños,
bean sprouts for sure,
a little bit of lime,
and a touch of Sriracha.
There we go.
Now!
Mmm!
The broth is outrageous.
The brisket's sliced
nice and thin.
Mmm.
In my world of pho,
this is one of the best.
Thank you.
I wish I could get in it.
Just so much flavor
and so much depth.
MAN:
It tastes super-fresh.
You can taste all the
ingredients that go into it.
I love squeezing the lime in it.
That's kind of the icing
on the cake.
Out of bounds.
I'll finish the soup.
You can go.
You can leave now.
Up next,
we're flying out to Oahu...
That's real-deal,
local-style Hawaiian.
...for island family recipes...
That's a big,
hearty plate of ribs.
...that locals are calling
legit.
That's how we do it here.
I'm here on the island of Oahu.
When I roll to places like this,
I like to get off
the beaten path
and eat where the locals eat.
So I'm about a half-mile
from Kailua Beach,
one of the greatest beaches
in the islands,
and I'm here to check out
a joint
that is loved by the tourists
and the locals.
This is Boots & Kimo's.
JESSIE:
Pulehu ribs up.
The way that they cook it,
it's just perfect.
Very local Hawaiian-style food.
FIERI: Something Boots Kiakona
found hard to come by
in the local food scene
20 years ago.
He had a dream of putting
a restaurant together,
'cause it Kailua,
it didn't have anything.
FIERI: Until his boys, Rick
and Jessie, honored that dream
by partnering up
with their uncle Kimo
to open this joint in '94.
And it is what it is today --
Boots & Kimo's.
The food is really 'ono.
'Ono means "very delicious"
in Hawaiian.
Local favorites
like short ribs...
Chicken and always garlic,
katsu, Korean, mochiko.
The mochiko chicken.
WOMAN: Thank you.
Enjoy.
Mochiko?
Yeah.
Mochiko is a sweet flour.
What do you got?
Give it to me.
Some chicken thighs here.
Boneless chicken thighs --
skin on.
So you run the kitchen,
your brother runs
the front of the house?
Yes.
Pretty much.
Where'd all the recipes
come from?
From my mother, my father,
and my Uncle Kimo.
Okay.
So everybody had a hand in this.
Now we're gonna make
the marinade?
Yes.
We have some sugar.
This is the mochiko flour.
It's rice -- sweet flour.
Cornstarch.
Sea salt.
So now in here?
I can't believe you already
got me working.
I know.
Next up.
Okay. Some garlic.
There you go.
Some water.
A little soy sauce?
And a little soy sauce.
And that's it.
Did you want to put
the pepper in?
Yes.
I did miss the pepper.
Pour in the bowl.
Add the green onion.
My egg mixture.
So now the chicken
in here?
The chicken.
Let it marinate,
then we'll fry it.
Yeah.
There you go.
How many pieces
are you giving me?
You look a little
on the thin side.
I'm not gonna get invited
to the luau like this, am I?
And what does it
get served with?
Rice
and macaroni potato salad.
The staples.
Mmm.
That little bit of marinade made
that much of a difference --
really worked the flavor
in there.
Mmm.
It's great, buddy.
I mean, it's simple.
It's straightforward.
Mmm.
It's got great taste.
A little bit of sweetness.
Excellent.
I dig it.
Mochiko chicken up.
It's very flavorful.
It's crispy on the outside,
soft and moist on the inside,
and it goes well
with the macaroni salad.
One of the best mochiko chickens
I've ever had.
WOMAN:
Chicken katsu.
Everybody comes here --
Korea, Japan, Philippines.
FIERI: And especially welcome
are Denver Bronco fans.
Another John Elway pic--
I mean John,
you got to come here.
John watches "Triple D."
Hey, listen, Elway.
This is like the clubhouse
away from Denver.
But the greatest fans here begin
and end at the menu.
MAN:
Kalbi ribs up.
Kalbi ribs -- That's high
on the list here for must-order.
It's like a sweet soy marinade,
and it's grilled.
What are we making?
Hawaiian-style kalbi ribs.
Need some sugar,
some black pepper,
some sesame seeds,
Hawaiian chili pepper,
some garlic.
Sesame oil?
Sesame oil.
Hawaiian papaya,
some green onion, soy sauce.
And some water.
How long will this marinate
on the ribs?
I marinate this
for two days.
It's like a meat waterfall
in Flavortown.
We ready to go
on the grill?
Ready to go.
Here you go.
That's a big,
hearty plate of ribs.
Mmm.
The flavor is outrageous.
Big. Rich.
A little spice to it,
a little sweet.
Just look at that.
Great hot char on it.
It's not just sweet.
There's a little touch
of some heat in there.
It is really tender.
Mmm.
That's real-deal,
local-style Hawaiian.
That's how we do it here.
No wonder you do so well.
Kalbi ribs up.
WOMAN:
Super tasty and juicy.
They have a lot of good fat
and flavor in them.
It's like if you were to do it
at home,
but it's even better than that.
Really 'ono, and we like that.
Amazing tribute that you did
for your dad and your uncle.
I think that's what makes this
really happen.
Food's delicious,
and it's just really good
old-school Hawaiian, man.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Nice.
Go, Raiders.
[ Laughs ]
So that's it for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
MAN:
We're done with the scene.
We can, uh...
[ Laughter ]
Do you really like that?
It's phenomenal.
I thought he was just acting.
[ Laughs ]
No. No. No.