I'm Guy Fieri, and we're rolling
out on a special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" in Hawaii.
This trip...
Oh, no.
...we're cruising
around Oahu, Hawaii...
Wow.
...for a tasty tour
of island flavor.
Soon as I do this,
nine buttons are gonna
break off this shirt.
First, at Kaneohe...
Have a fish just like that
in my aquarium.
...a drive-in that comes off
as casual...
He's a butchering madman.
...but is busting out
gourmet goodness.
Fine dining in Styrofoam.
Then a walk
on the wild side...
Are you a friendly bear?
Yeah,
but like gangster one.
Like, "Raar."
...at a joint mixing
Hawaiian favs
with international flair.
Give you the wham, bam,
and the "thank you, ma'am."
Plus, a family-run hangout
in Waipahu...
Look at this, dude.
...with a different
island style.
Where's Filipino food been
all my life?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D" in Hawaii.
So, this is the first stop on
the Great Hawaiian Island Tour.
Now, I'm in Kaneohe,
right on the Kamehameha Highway.
I love coming to this island.
I've had great
"Triple D" joints. Let's see.
Fresh Catch, Opal Thai,
Rainbow Drive-In --
Drive-in?
You know when I hear that,
I got to stop and check it out.
This is Dean's Drive Inn.
Dean's has probably the best
local food I've ever had.
They always got fresh fish.
MAN:
It tastes like they belong
in some five-star restaurant
in Waikiki.
FIERI: That's because
owner Dean Mishima brought along
40 years of experience when
he opened his own place in 2006.
Teri beef steak
and boneless short-rib cutlet.
And he's keeping it
in the family
with wife Doreen
running the front
and daughter Melissa helping out
in the back.
DEAN:
Beef cutlet, coming up.
And Dean's cooking up
casual gourmet
with a style
I'm definitely digging.
I like the bleach, man.
And the locals are liking
what Dean's serving up.
This is a ginger soy ono.
FIERI: Ono -- that would be
the popular Hawaiian whitefish,
a.k.a. wahoo.
It's really nice.
It's fresh.
Oh, no.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, no. All right.
You know how to butcher fish,
I take it.
I know how to butcher
fish.
I'm impressed.
Now we're gonna portion it up,
grill it.
Grill it, put on
a nice soy ginger sauce.
All right.
First, ginger.
Okay.
Garlic.
Green onion.
Black pepper.
Salt.
Here we go.
[ Motor whirring ]
You're gonna kill
that little thing.
Kill that thing!
All right.
Now we're gonna top it off
with this hot oil here.
Okay.
Bring out the flavor.
So, it doesn't really
cook it.
It just kind of opens it,
get the real perfume of it.
Yeah.
Now we grill the fish,
and that goes on the fish.
Right.
Dig it.
I'm gonna be dusting it
with a little flour.
Okay, ono.
Ono, ono.
Grilling it
to a golden brown.
What temperature
do you serve that at?
Medium.
All right.
Soy sauce.
There we go.
Wow.
That's ridiculous flavor, Chef.
Ridiculous.
Little bit of ginger...
...green onion,
little soy.
Simply prepared,
simply seasoned,
simply outrageous.
Outstanding.
It's got a light taste
of ginger.
MAN: Not too strong,
and it's not too mild.
It's just right.
How do you explain
Dean's Drive Inn?
It's fine dining.
Just in Styrofoam.
Oh, yeah.
Favorite thing
on the menu.
By far, the ahi cakes.
Hands down.
I have a fish just like that
in my aquarium.
What fish is this?
It's a yellowfin tuna.
Wow.
Boy, you get after this.
Look at that.
It's gorgeous.
Okay. Now we're gonna make
the cakes.
Right.
Put in some of these onions,
water chestnut,
green onions, black pepper.
Black pepper, okay.
Soy sauce,
put in your eggs.
All-purpose flour.
All of it?
All of it.
Okay.
And mix it up.
And mix it.
Massage this fish.
You're gonna massage it.
That's why it tastes
so good.
Just enough
to bind it together.
All right, let's make a cake,
baby.
Okay.
And we serve this medium rare
or cooked all the way through?
Golden brown
on both sides.
All right.
Greek chili aioli sauce.
Your little garnish
is beautiful.
Well, Chef,
your flavors are great.
And butchering the tuna,
using all the parts of the fish,
very impressive.
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
The ahi cakes are moist.
There's a little crunch in them.
To die for.
It's really, really good.
What else you got for me?
Broiled teriyaki beef.
Teriyaki beef --
it is wonderful.
It's got great flavor.
All right, then.
Let's make some teriyaki beef.
All right.
FIERI: When we come back.
FIERI: Right now,
"Triple D's" hanging loose
on the island of Oahu
at Dean's Drive Inn.
But don't judge the food
by its Styrofoam box.
This chef's putting high-end
into his Hawaiian.
Just really good food.
All right, Chef,
now what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
a broiled beef teriyaki.
You know what I'm using here
is a bottom sirloin.
Delicious.
Great flavor.
Just got to cook it the right
way and cut it the right way.
Mm-hmm.
He's butchering madman.
So, tenderize it
a little bit.
Now stack it up, and we're gonna
make the marinade.
Exactly.
All right, we'll be doing
some teriyaki sauce.
Soy sauce.
Sugar.
Water.
Ginger and some garlic.
Ginger, garlic -- got it.
Just gonna pour that right over
the beef and that's it.
Pour it right over the beef.
And how long will that
marinate?
Marinate it overnight.
Okay, this is the teri beef
that I just cut and marinated.
Cook it up
about medium, medium rare.
Ready to go, Chef?
Ready.
Like butter, baby.
That's right.
And what's that
that's going on there?
It's a teriyaki sauce.
Garnish.
That is
so ridiculously tender.
Top-selling item.
I can see why.
Great texture,
super-tender,
little bit
on the sweet side.
Outrageous, Chef.
Thank you.
It's one of my favorites.
The teri sauce here
is great.
It's crazy.
It's delicious.
After a day in the ocean,
nothing beats this.
Dean's is
just quality Hawaiian food.
Forget about it.
Well done.
Thank you.
Well done, Chef.
I am so glad I don't live
next to you.
[ Laughs ]
Trade the convertible in
for, like, a dump truck.
FIERI: Coming up
on our island tour of Oahu...
Really outstanding.
This will be one I remember.
...fresh island ingredients
in Kailua...
That is exactly
how it's supposed to be done.
...twisted up and topped off
with one of my favs.
I've almost eaten
all of it.
So, I'm here
on the windward side of Oahu
in a little town named Kailua.
Now, what do you get
when you come over here?
Well, you get awesome beaches.
I mean,
they got a bowling alley,
got all kinds of shops
around here,
but the question is,
where do you eat?
Well, that's where I come in
to help out,
'cause I've heard about
a funky little joint
where they're serving up
Hawaiian classics with a twist.
This is Uahi Island Grill.
The food in this place
is spectacular.
CHEF:
Got your lemongrass shrimp here.
Flavorful without being
too spicy.
It's more of like
an Asian fusion kind of mix.
FIERI: A mix that owners
Nick Yamada and Nani Nikcevich
have called
"contemporary Hawaiian"...
NIKCEVICH:
Korean steak salad.
...ever since they first
fired up their grill in 2007.
Does this say "Chef Bear"?
Sure does.
Are you a friendly bear?
Yeah.
Very nice.
But like a gangster one.
What does a gangster bear's claw
look like?
Like, "Raar."
[ Chuckles ]
This wild spirit led to
exploring Southeast Asia
for some culinary inspiration.
Putting the red curry
grilled fish up in the window.
The red curry fish is amazing.
It's got a nice combination
of sweetness and spice.
The texture is perfect
with the green papaya salad.
What're we gonna make?
We're making
our red curry grilled fish.
This is hebi. It's a locally
caught shortbill spearfish.
How do you spell it?
H-e-b-i.
And it's actually
pretty light.
So, it's light,
but it's "hebi."
Yeah, exactly.
What would it
compare to?
It's kind of in between
a mahimahi and a marlin.
Okay.
And I just like to do
these bias cuts on an angle.
That's it.
But we're gonna make
a red curry sauce.
Yeah.
So, I'm gonna start off
by sautéing this red curry.
Hit it with some fish sauce
real quick.
Some lemon juice, brown sugar,
coconut milk.
Okay.
I'll bring it up to a boil.
We're gonna hit it with
a cornstarch slurry to
thicken it up a little bit.
And the ice is for?
To cool it down
and to bring it
to that consistency
that we want.
Gives you the wham, bam,
and the "thank you, ma'am."
Okay.
Green papaya salad.
That is gonna top the hebi.
So, we're gonna grate
this green papaya.
The texture in this
is crunchy.
Little green-appleish.
Gonna get all the green papaya
in here.
Tomato, grated carrot,
red bell pepper,
cilantro.
And now we're gonna dress this
with fish sauce.
Lemon juice.
Brown sugar, equal parts.
Now we're gonna whisk that
together.
Love papaya salad.
This is all for me, right?
Yes, it is.
Oh!
That is exactly
how it's supposed to be done.
So, we're just gonna take
a little portion of this hebi,
just get a little salt
on there.
And then we're gonna
slap it on the grill.
I like to cook it just to where
it's not quite done,
a little bit pink
in the middle.
So, now we're just
gonna plate it up.
You can get
brown rice here.
I'm a big brown-rice fan.
I'm also
a green-papaya-salad fan.
You are in
the right place.
I've almost eaten
all of it.
I'm just gonna get it
right on the rice.
We're gonna top it
with our red curry
that we've brought back up
to temperature.
And that is it.
I just got the acid
of the vinaigrette,
sweetness of the fish.
You have great textures.
The richness of the curry
but the char of the fish.
It's what really gives it
this -- this island flavor.
Really outstanding.
This will be one I remember.
Awesome, man.
Every bite just gets soaked
in the flavor.
Gourmet plate lunch.
The fish is fresh-caught,
you know that
he's sourcing things locally.
FIERI:
And they're punching up
those Hawaiian ingredients
with a twist.
Got a mandarin duck confit
coming out.
The orange glaze adds
that extra little sweetness
and oomph to the dish.
So, we're gonna take
our duck legs,
arrange them here
in this pan.
So, we are going to flat-out
confit this.
Now, is this duck fat
from other confitings?
This is rendered duck fat
from other confitings.
Confitings.
We're just gonna cover this.
Get some star anise in there.
It's the star of the show.
[ Record scratches ]
Well...
Besides yourself.
Oven, 250.
For?
Four hours.
Nice.
Next up.
Now we're making the orange
glaze for the duck confit.
Okay.
Orange juice, rice vinegar,
shoyu, star anise,
sugar,
and a little ginger.
Got it.
And at this stage, we're just
gonna incorporate the sugar,
just bring it up.
Just till it dissolves.
And per order,
we're gonna glaze it down.
Got it.
Duck's ready.
Hit it.
We'll get it out of the oven
here.
Gorgeous.
I like to do
1 1/2 pieces of these.
I keep one whole,
and I shred one.
And then we put on the flat top
to crisp up the skin.
Crisp it up?
Yeah.
All right,
so the duck is crisped up.
Great.
Again, two scoops of rice.
Put the shredded meat...
And I put
this whole one...
Right up on top.
And from here,
I'm gonna get our choy sum,
which is
a Chinese broccoli.
Right there.
And last but not least...
We got our orange glaze.
Just get the glaze
all over the plate, there.
A lot of star anise,
which...
has great flavor itself.
But it's much deeper
and much more complex.
The way this
has come together
with the glaze
that you put on top of it...
You got the right balance
of the sugar.
It's spot-on, man.
Outstanding.
It's real sweet and yummy
and tender.
They love what they do,
and it shows.
You have got
a really subtle hand...
but deliver
a lot of big flavor.
Thank you.
Great job. Wow!
I appreciate it.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI:
Up next, one more Oahu stop...
That was just awesome.
...in Waipahu.
A joint going hog wild...
You got a party
in your mouth.
...with an out-of-bounds
pork trifecta.
Fried chicharrón and a rib
and baked at the same time.
So, here's the final stop
on this awesome Hawaiian Island
"Triple D" tour.
Now, I'm about 10 miles west
of downtown Honolulu
in an area known as Waipahu.
Huge Filipino community.
And I'm thinking,
"You know what?
We haven't done a lot
of Filipino food on "Triple D."
That's where my boy Reno
from Fresh Catch comes in.
You remember that character.
Hyah!
He says, "Dude, I got a joint
you got to check out.
The food rocks the house."
This is Elena's.
Your fried pork is ready.
I go to his restaurant,
Fresh Catch. Why this place?
This place
feels like home, bro.
The closest I can get
to a home-cooked meal.
FIERI:
And there's a reason for that.
Let's just say
that owner Richard Butuyan
has a very personal connection
with the original owner.
Who's Elena?
It's my mom.
Your mom's Elena?
Yes.
My mom started it.
That was back in '74.
Now Richard's running the joint
with his sister Mellissa,
and they're still cooking up
mom's Filipino favorites.
Gisantes is ready.
How do you describe
Filipino food?
Uh, how do you put it?
It's a mixture
of Spanish and Chinese.
Wow.
FIERI:
Which all comes together
on this pork-on-pork feast
of belly and fried rice.
Lechon special.
Thank you.
Love the pork, the tomatoes,
the onions.
Just goes perfect, hand-in-hand
with each other.
All right, so what is the first
dish we're gonna make?
We're gonna make
lechon special.
So, we start
with the pork belly.
We're gonna cut all this
into cubes.
Yeah.
Skin on and everything?
Skin on.
Okay, so these aren't cubes.
Those are chunks.
Chunks, yeah.
Gonna boil it first.
Boil it away.
So, where are we now?
We're gonna make some pork
with a little fried rice.
Pork adobo.
Yeah.
Oil. Got to be careful.
Start with some rice,
fry it up.
Get it going.
Soy sauce.
Oyster sauce.
And then some black pepper.
Garlic powder.
Mix it up a little.
You know,
get the color in.
Now we're gonna add
some pork adobo.
And what does the "adobo"
mean?
Vinegary.
Mix it up.
Mash it down.
Now we're done
with this?
We're done with this.
Great.
Mmm. Oh.
That's not a dish?
Yeah, we're gonna add
the lechon special to that.
All right.
The pork belly.
Now we're gonna deep-fry
this?
Yes.
Look at that.
You want to get some tongs?
Nah. Aah.
Got it, I got it.
Chop it up.
That's crazy.
A chicharrón and a rib
and baked at the same time.
Now we're gonna add
the chopped tomatoes.
Chopped onions.
Fish sauce.
Hawaiian sea salt.
Green onions.
Put this on here?
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, then I'll just
put it on.
I love
where we're going with this --
little bit of acid,
hot pork.
Soon as I do this,
nine buttons are gonna
break off this shirt.
How do you like it?
It's awesome.
[ Chuckles ]
Crunchy pork, the skin,
the fat, the tender meat.
You put that fresh tomato
in there...
You got a party
in your mouth.
[ Laughing ]
That's legit. Awesome.
MAN: The lechon is
my favorite dish here.
It's like a flavor explosion.
Is this
true Filipino food?
It's true Filipino food,
but, eh, we made it
Hawaiian-style.
CEDILLO: Fried pork.
Now what are we making?
We're gonna make
some fried pork.
Okay.
So, we're starting out
with the pork butt.
So we're just gonna
slice it thin.
This is a boneless pork butt.
Boneless pork butt.
We're gonna make
the marinade.
Raw onions, bay leaves,
fresh garlic,
garlic powder,
some black pepper,
Hawaiian sea salt...
Apple-cider vinegar.
Put in the pork.
How long we gonna marinate
the pork?
We marinate it
for about a day.
We're gonna make
a pickled ong choy.
Pickled ong choy.
For a side dish
for the fried pork.
What is ong choy?
In English,
it's water spinach.
We're only gonna use
the stems.
You don't use
the leaves?
No.
That's for another dish.
And we just cut it up.
Here, so we're gonna make
the marinade.
Okay.
We're gonna start off with
onions, some fresh garlic,
garlic powder,
some black pepper,
Hawaiian chili pepper,
and some Hawaiian salt.
And we're gonna finish it off
with some vinegar.
This marinates
for a few days.
And that goes
with the fried pork.
I cook it in the skillet
'cause if I put it
in the deep-fryer,
it's gonna get hard,
like pork jerky.
Cut it up while it's hot.
Look at this, dude.
Outrageous.
Lots of flavor.
Little vinegar sauce.
This is
what really makes it.
Ong choy.
Little bit of vinegar,
little bit of heat,
little bit of crunch,
little veggie piece to it.
Your mom's out of bounds,
bro.
[ Chuckles ]
Elena.
Congrats, man.
Very tasty.
That vinegar just bites at you.
I got to tell you
something,
where's Filipino food been
all my life?
This is where it's at.
I know why Reno said,
"Come check it out."
It's the real deal, man.
All right, man.
Thanks, brother.
So, that's it for this trip!
And don't worry -- there's
plenty more "Triple D" joints
all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
This is
a really nice one.
That's Randall.
Randall?
Randall.
You named it?
Yeah.
Randall, Randall,
has no handle.
Exactly.
[ Laughs ]