Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Imitating
Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
We're tag-teaming it now.
...we're checking out
new spins...
That's nuts.
...on some old standards.
Thank you.
That just changed it all.
In Jackson, Wyoming...
Whoa!
I like that.
...a real-deal pizza joint...
You're talking chew,
you're talking texture,
talking money.
...taking their pies
on a wild ride.
AUNT POLLY:
♪ How funky is your chicken?
♪ How loose is your goose? ♪
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Then in Long Beach,
California...
It is a power bomb
of flavor.
...scratch-made classics...
You're the scone-inator.
...getting a massive makeover.
This is a coma item.
And in Monterey, California...
[ Mumbling indistinctly ]
...the brew house
putting pub grub...
Every bite, just five more
minutes on the elliptical.
...on a first-place pedestal.
Look at that!
It's redonkulous.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here at Jackson, Wyoming,
about a half block
off the town square,
right in front
of the Pink Garter Theatre.
Now, back in the day,
this was the theater
that you came to
to catch a musical or a play.
Now it's where you come
to see some rocking bands.
And speaking of rocking,
locals around here tell me
if you want some rocking pizza,
you got to go to the joint
right under the theater.
This is Pinky G's Pizzeria.
I love the pizza at Pinky G's.
Hot and ready.
Come and get it.
I would say best pizza
in Wyoming.
Real nice.
What do you like
about this place?
The pizza's
the size of my head.
It's a good deal.
FIERI: These pizzas
are the creation
of chef and owner Tom Fay,
who came back home
after culinary school
and opened this joint in 2011.
When did you get
the brain child
to open up the pizza joint?
FAY: Knowing that we needed
to fill a niche in town,
I served pizza
by the slice and --
So, no one was doing pizza
by the slice?
No.
Just needed to be
up to par.
We needed some good pizza
in town.
Funky chicken.
I love
the funky chicken pizza.
WOMAN: It's probably one
of the most delicious pieces
of pizza I've had.
Time to get down
with the funky chicken.
Starts with the chicken.
Chicken breasts.
Some fresh, chopped basil.
A boatload of garlic.
Lemon slices.
And oil.
So, how long we gonna let
this marinade?
24 hours.
24 hours, then to a sheet pan,
then in the oven.
And we're gonna cook it
at this 525?
[ Whistles ]
575.
All right,
how long we been in?
25 minutes.
That smells awesome.
Gonna dust the peel here.
Is this cornmeal and flour?
Yep.
You hand-throw all this?
Hand-toss.
It's the only way to go.
Whoa!
Yeah.
I like that.
Okay, first up, pesto.
Fresh basil pesto.
Mozzarella cheese.
Roasted chicken.
Artichoke hearts.
Red onions.
And ricotta cheese.
Here we go.
575.
For how long?
10 minutes.
Look at that.
That's not hot at all.
When the pesto's boiling
on the pizza, note to self --
Let it cool?
Let it cool, fool.
Roasting the chicken
with the garlic --
outrageous.
Making your own pesto,
over the top.
Little bit of that ricotta
coming in,
creaminess, saltiness.
How did you come up
with the name funky chicken?
Funky chicken is just one
of my favorite dances.
Okay.
There's one other person
that I know the funky chicken
is one
of her favorite dances.
Let's get Aunt Polly
on the phone.
AUNT POLLY: Hey, honey.
Hi, Aunt Polly.
How are you?
I'm at a joint
in Jackson, Wyoming,
and they have a pizza
called...the funky chicken.
[ Laughing ] No way.
Can you give me
a little funky chicken?
Sure.
Okay, here we go.
You ready?
♪ How funky is your chicken? ♪
♪ How loose is your goose? ♪
[ Laughs ]
All right, all right.
Thank you, Polly.
[ Laughs ]
Funky chicken.
How do you go wrong?
I really like how there's a lot
of creativity with the pizza.
All right,
Abe Froman coming up.
Sausage, cheese, basil.
You put those things together
on just about anything,
it's gonna taste good.
FIERI: What pizza
are we gonna make?
The Abe Froman.
Abe Froman,
the sausage king of Chicago
from "Ferris Bueller's
Day Off"?
Yes.
I'm impressed
with the throw, man,
especially with
such low ceilings.
Let's add some sauce.
Nice amount of sauce.
I like this.
Mozzarella cheese.
Some spicy Italian sausage.
Buffalo mozz here.
Okay, go for it.
Let's do it.
Nice.
Little fresh basil
on top.
Should I just --
oh, you're gonna cut it.
I thought I was gonna eat
the whole thing.
There we go.
This'll take a week
to cool down.
The dough has got
awesome yeast flavor.
Sauce is tangy.
You're talking chew,
you're talking texture,
talking money.
18-inch Abe Froman
ready to go.
Has hot sausage
and plenty of cheese.
It's delicious.
MAN: I love this place.
Tom and his crew do a great job,
put a lot of love
into the product
they put across the table.
From the Abe Froman
to the funky chicken,
no wonder everybody in town
loves you.
It's off the hook, bro.
Great job.
Thanks, man.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Long Beach, California...
Girl, you were born to do
what you're doing.
...the see-it-every-day combo
of special scones...
What's in that scone?
...and a killer take
on pot roast.
And that's the masterpiece.
So, I'm here on 3rd Street
in Long Beach, California,
in an area known
as Belmont Heights.
Now, 10 minutes that way,
you're in downtown.
10 minutes that way,
you're at Long Beach State.
Now, I'm told that if this joint
had been in business
when I lived here,
I never would've moved.
This is Starling Diner.
You had the French toast with
the seasonal berries today?
This place is my happy place.
Crab cakes up, please.
The food is just fabulous.
Roast beef hash to you.
It's homemade.
It's always good.
They know what they're doing.
FIERI:
They is Joan Samson...
Twice-baked granola.
...who started in the biz
at age 10
running a snack shack out
of her parents' garage.
Stuffed French toast up.
Then college took her down
a different path.
I went
to Rutgers University.
What did you go
to Rutgers for?
For law.
You're an attorney?
I have a law degree.
WOMAN:
Breakfast polenta.
FIERI:
But instead of taking the bar,
she opened up some restaurants,
including this spot in '07.
Doesn't matter what you do.
End up
back in the restaurant.
They just suck you
back in.
I think it's just the love
that she has for food
and making the food.
Every dish has its
own unique twist.
SAMSON:
Pot roast bundle, please.
It's just phenomenal.
We're gonna do our
slow-roasted pot roast.
It's wrapped in our tortilla
with polenta and potatoes.
All right,
let's get it going.
We start by searing
chuck roast in butter.
So, we're seared off.
Next step?
Then we add the mirepoix,
which is celery, carrots,
onions, herbs, rosemary --
my favorite.
Little thyme.
Bay leaf.
Peppercorns.
Thank you.
Wow.
And a lot of garlic.
A lot of garlic.
This is the stock
from the last time
this was made?
Absolutely.
I like the way
you're rolling.
And how much wine
are you and I gonna drink?
[ Laughs ]
And then salt and pepper.
Okay. Wow.
Then we tuck it all in.
How long
we gonna cook it?
4 to 6 hours.
Got it.
275.
Okay.
There we go.
Okay, we're making
polenta potatoes.
We've got mashed potatoes
that we mixed
with organic polenta.
We put them
in the salamander
to get that nice crisp top
on it.
Take the pot roast out
of the oven.
Got it.
[ Whistles ]
It's looking sexy.
Here we go
with the potato polenta.
That's nuts.
And then a layer
of caramelized onions.
Find some great pieces
for you.
Pour gravy inside.
Fold it, flip it.
And yet there's more.
Top it off with gravy.
Gonna make it healthy.
There we go. We're gonna waft it
with some lettuce.
With a little bit
of parsley.
Thank you.
That just changed it all.
The gravy is ridiculous.
Creaminess of the potato,
texture of the polenta,
the rich pot roast.
It is a power bomb
of flavor.
[ Laughs ]
Warning, don't eat this
and drive.
This is a coma item.
It's juicy, it's savory,
it's wonderful.
Seriously, it's like
your mother's pot roast.
Hey!
Every time I come in,
I get a hug from Joan.
I feel like I belong here.
I'm the mailman here.
This is a stop on my route.
This is your joint?
I have scones every day.
Every day.
SAMSON:
Scones up, please.
They're light and fluffy.
Unlike anything I've ever had.
This was the first item
on the menu?
Yeah.
I love it. Let's go.
Start
with all-purpose flour.
Sugar.
Little bit of salt.
Baking powder.
I'm gonna massage it.
Get those mixed evenly.
Cold butter.
And then
you're gonna knead it
until it gets to the texture
of cornmeal.
Then we add
the heavy cream.
Okay.
Now we have to work
lightly.
So, I'm just bringing
these things together
until they want to get together
on their own.
You're like the dating service
of Flavortown.
That's a scone.
That's what it's supposed
to look like.
That's a scone.
We're gonna cut them
into wedges.
Equal-size wedges.
Okay.
These go in the oven
for how long?
For 18 to 20 minutes,
depending on your oven.
We give three
to a basket.
No, you don't.
Yes, we do.
You're the scone-inator.
And then that
is orange honey butter.
Mmm.
This is about the lightest,
fluffiest, tender scone
I think I've ever tried.
I've just had a lot of scones
I don't like,
dried out and fortified
with all kinds of berries
and nuts and things and such.
Yeah.
♪ Berries and nuts
and things and such ♪
[ Laughs ]
What's in that scone?
Basket of scones to you.
WOMAN:
They're just really delicious.
It's not too sweet,
so it's a really great mix.
Every single time,
it's just amazing.
WOMAN #2: You feel happy,
and you can't wait to get back.
Once you come here, you're like
you don't want to leave.
Girl, you were born
to be in the business.
You were born to do
what you're doing.
Don't forget that.
I won't.
FIERI: Up next, we're cruising
up the coast to Monterey...
That's outrageous.
...to a bayside taproom
going all out...
This came off
of a dinosaur cow.
...to dress up the menu.
That's not a skirt.
That's a full prom dress.
So, I'm here
in Monterey, California,
one of the coolest towns
you will find
on the California coast.
Now, when you pull into town,
you're gonna want to come
check out this joint.
It is scratch-making
their own menu,
and has got a tap handle list
you are gonna love.
This is the Cannery Row
Brewing Company.
You're in a bar,
but the food's sophisticated.
Smoked chicken nachos.
I love this place.
Got the hot wings.
FIERI: This yin-yang approach
to high-end bar grub
opened in 2010
when local restaurateurs
Rob Weakley and Dave Bernahl
decided on something
a little different.
You guys own a bunch
of restaurants,
but this is
a one-of-a-kind.
Yeah, absolutely.
We've got families
that are coming here,
we've got die-hard beer heads
that come here.
We've got this big mix,
so we wanted to create
a space that was unique,
but also was welcoming
to everyone.
And heading up the culinary
welcome wagon is Chef Dan Furey,
who embraced his high-end past
when putting a twist
on an old-fashioned staple.
FUREY:
Parmesan pretzel in the window.
This pretzel is the best pretzel
I've ever had.
WOMAN: There's a big old bowl
of cheese dip on the side,
and it's got beer in it,
so you get
that nice little contrast
and a little bit
of spice, too.
What is the pretzel
actually called?
Parmesan pretzel.
We put a little bit of decent
parmesan cheese in there.
Well, get after this
before I eat all the cheese.
So, we take our yeast,
put it in.
And then just
a little bit of flour.
Just sits for a minute.
The fresh yeast activates
with the water.
All right, so it sat up.
Yep.
Now we put the rest
of the ingredients in.
We got
the parmesan cheese.
Olive oil.
And then
we add the sugar now.
Little bit
of iodized salt.
And then the rest
of the flour.
Pull it up.
All right, so how long
is this gonna knead?
6 to 8 minutes.
Really? Okay.
It'll form together.
You ready?
18 ounces of this.
Yep.
I kind of pull it
into a rectangle
and just kind of roll in
and pinch.
Push down
with your thumbs.
All right, so usually I start
and stretch it a little bit.
All right, and then
you make a big "U."
Twist, twist, pull down,
and you push pretty hard.
And you got your pretzel.
And that's all she wrote.
Let it proof how long?
About five minutes.
Then we'll drop it
into the simmering water.
With a little bit
of baking soda,
and that's what builds
the crust on it
that everybody loves.
Yeah, you get that nice brown,
little bit of chew to it.
The pretzel's gonna float.
There we go.
Starting to float.
So, I have the...
Doctor.
...super-technical --
Of course you do.
Yeah, definitely.
Brush it with
a little garlic butter.
Sprinkle with some salt.
Little pretzel salt on there.
You're good to go.
The oven is at what temp?
350.
For how long?
About 6 minutes, spin,
another 6 minutes.
Want to make sure you get
a nice, even, brown coat.
All right, chef,
pretzel's cooking.
Let's make
some cheese sauce.
Little bit of butter.
Little A.P. flour here.
Have Korean chili flake.
Got a little black pepper.
Little salt, doctor.
Salt.
Mustard.
Hot sauce, doctor.
Doctor.
Doctor doctor.
Any kind of particular
hot sauce?
It's a little Sriracha
and Tabasco mixed.
Worcestershire sauce.
And then we got
a good Belgian ale.
I like it.
A little veg stock.
You make yourself,
of course.
Yeah,
we make the veg stock.
Got a little cream.
Little cheddar cheese.
Look at that.
It's redonkulous.
All right, cheese sauce.
Cheese sauce.
You hate it.
I can tell.
You're not enjoying that
at all.
Every bite is five more minutes
on the elliptical.
[ Chuckles ]
It's delicious.
Not super heavy
and dense.
The garlic-butter touch
on the outside,
that's outrageous.
Chef, outstanding.
Nice job.
Thank you so much.
WOMAN: Parmesan pretzel.
Amazing pretzel.
It's a little bit crisp
on the bottom,
but it sits perfect with that
nice, soft, doughy inside.
It's my good buddy,
Teddy Balestreri.
Do you have a favorite item
on the menu?
This is my favorite.
Better than New York.
Better than Bavaria.
And he's been to both places
several times this week.
Okay, what are
we gonna do next?
FUREL:
A short rib grilled cheese.
It's very tender,
very cheesy.
It's absolutely amazing.
FIERI: When we come back.
FIERI: Right now, Triple "D" is
parked in Monterey, California,
at the Cannery Row
Brewing Company,
where they're cooking up
the bomb bar food.
WOMAN: I love it. Everything is
just done with such quality
and, like, amazing flavor.
I have the short rib
grilled cheese. Amazing.
MAN: It's kind of like
a supercharged grilled cheese.
It's got the crusted parmesan on
the outside, which is delicious.
So, the short rib
grilled cheese.
Now, these are real-deal
short ribs.
FUREL: They're 3-bone,
6-inch cut.
Yeah, this came off
of a dinosaur cow.
Give me the rundown.
Little salt and pepper.
[ Imitating
Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
We're tag-teaming it now.
[ Normal voice ] Okay.
We got a super-hot pan.
Just a little bit
of canola olive oil.
Lay it in.
So, we'll sear off
both sides.
We pull these guys out,
and you want to have the flavor
in the bottom of the pan.
Little onion.
Celery.
Carrots.
Little tomato paste.
Cook that out.
Little red wine.
Deglaze the pan.
It's gonna pull that love
off the bottom.
Pull the love
Little veal stock.
And a little fresh thyme.
Bay leaf.
Okay, so this is all
cooked down.
Short ribs back in.
Yep.
Throw these in there.
Put the bone side up
so you get the meat nice
in the juice.
Throw a little foil on there
and we'll get them in the oven.
How long we go
in the oven for?
About 3½ hours.
Till they're just pull-apart
tender, but not falling apart.
All right, chef,
short ribs are done.
Short ribs are done.
We got our bread.
We toasted it
on the flattop
with just a little bit
of provolone.
That's not a skirt.
That's a full prom dress.
We got
oven-roasted tomatoes.
Got our short rib.
Pickled Fresno chili.
Arugula
and citrus vinaigrette.
Nice local goat cheese.
This is ridiculous.
Couple extra chilies in case
you want it for later.
In case you're just not
completely out of your mind.
Cut into it.
Got a little bit of clam chowder
going on here.
Oyster cracker.
Little chiffonade parsley.
And then sandwich,
kind of lay it in there.
Got in there.
[ Mumbles indistinctly ]
[ Laughs ]
Starting
at the cheese prom dress --
crunchy, tear it off,
bite it like fried cheese.
Toasted bread perfectly.
Short rib
is just unctuous.
Awesome.
Cut of fat as soon as you bring
that pickled Fresno chili.
Little tang
from the goat cheese.
I mean, you're just hitting
level after level.
You're bouncing
like a pinball in there.
Every bite
is exactly right.
And then the chowder --
you guys also make this?
Yep.
This is...
without question,
one of the best clam chowders
I've ever had.
Outstanding, chef.
Thank you.
I understand
why Dave and Rob have you.
That means a lot.
Thank you very much.
Short rib grilled cheese,
clam chowder up!
WOMAN: Really crunchy,
crispy on the outside,
and the inside has just
so much flavor.
It's an amazing sandwich.
It's sandwich-tastic.
MAN: It's really unique
because there's, like,
a parmesan tuile almost,
like a parmesan crust.
Tuile?
That's a --
the tuile is this big.
That is like
a parmesan wheel.
It's a blanket.
Yes, it is.
WOMAN: They do a fantastic job
with the menu here,
and they really care
about the food.
There's really nothing else
like it.
Nicely done.
Thanks, brother.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Do I have any on there?
No, no.
You're good.
Yeah. Here.
But right in here.
No, no.
It looks good.
I'm all right?
You're good.
You have buddies like that,
I mean, who can you count on?
Like a crime scene.