Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, boy.
...we're getting stuffed...
Oh, yeah.
...and twisted...
[ Laughs ]
...in Jackson, Wyoming.
Sports bar
with French onion soup.
That's not something
you see every day.
An all-American saloon
with Semper Fi spirit...
Don't ever call me
a chef.
...going way behind
rank-and-file food.
Gosh, I like
the way you roll.
Then,
in Monterey, California...
I'm getting a little
freaked out right now,
but I'll go
with what you got.
...a family-run Italian joint...
Nice job.
Mom did it right.
...where Mama
definitely knows best.
We have a rule -- can't
wear more bling than
the host of the show.
And in Boston,
Massachusetts...
Look at that.
...a funky
little sandwich shop...
It's outrageous.
...putting on
a full-court panini press.
Eating it?
I'm gonna devour it!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here in Jackson, Wyoming,
about a mile
from the downtown tourist area,
and you know me on "Triple D."
I don't want to go
where the tourists go.
I want to go
where the locals eat,
and I hear the joint
you got to check out
is Sidewinders
American Grill & Tavern.
RICE: Carne asada.
Sidewinders
is all about the food.
Barbecue burger up.
It's fresh, it's homemade, and
it's not trying to be too fancy.
FIERI: Just like its owner,
ex-marine Joe Rice.
I'm not a chef.
I'm a line cook.
Just remember that.
Don't ever call me a chef.
After flying jets,
Joe landed in the restaurant biz
and opened Sidewinders in '97,
naming it after the missiles
on an F-4 fighter jet.
Really a sports bar,
American grill
with really good
home-driven food.
The French onion soup's
to die for.
RICE: French onion soup!
This is my favorite soup to have
when I come here.
I appreciate
French onion soup,
and to find real-deal
French onion soup
would be, like, epic.
So, basically, we start
with some butter, olive oil.
Let that caramelize
a little bit.
We have Texas sweets,
regular whites, red onions,
leeks.
Then we'll sweat these down
just translucent.
A little salt.
Little garlic.
Little pepper.
Shallots.
Shallots have already been
sweated down?
Yes. Little thyme.
Stir that all in.
Add our sherry.
That's really the kicker.
A little bay leaf
and some beef stock?
You're making
your own beef stock.
Own beef stock.
How long
will we let this cook down?
About an hour.
First thing we do
is we put a crostini in.
Okay.
Just do a little of our --
the goodness, here.
Then a little --
Oh, boy.
[ Laughs ]
You're gonna screw this up,
aren't you?
[ Laughs ]
A little Gree.
I pride myself on not knowing
the real way to say this.
You know what? I think that's
good. I can't fly a plane.
How do you say that?
Gruyère.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
We're gonna take this
and put it in a Salamander.
To the Salamander
to melt the Gruyère.
Right.
Okay.
All right.
Sports bar
with French onion soup.
That's not something
you see every day.
This is great,
great French onion, man.
Thank you.
All the discipline is correct.
The crock makes it.
The way you cut the onions,
the variety of onions,
and the sherry level's
perfect.
The salt level's right.
The caramelization
isn't too far.
That's legit. Nice job.
Thank you.
The beef broth is to die for.
MAN:
It's a great balance between
the crouton and the cheese.
Wonderful taste.
I love the food because there's
such a variety on the menu.
The Carne asada.
Really?
Yeah.
WOMAN: Sidewinder pretzel.
I really love the "S" pretzel.
It's so good.
When I was a kid,
I had a business selling
soft, New York-style pretzels.
Had a little cart.
My foundation --
Now we give these carts away to
non-profit kids' organizations.
It's an all-American treat.
It's our number-one seller.
I can understand why.
All right. Let's get into it,
then. Give me the rundown.
We start with our yeast.
We bloom the yeast.
Once it's set up,
we start with olive oil.
A little salt.
Just a little honey.
All-purpose flour?
Yeah, high-gluten, all-purpose.
We'll pull this up.
Slowly add water.
Now we're gonna take it out
and portion it.
Get it on sheet trays,
put it in the refrigerator
for two hours to proof.
Then, when you're ready
to make a pretzel...
Just cut it in half
and put that aside.
You just kind of go
with your hand a little bit.
And what can you get this
stuffed with?
You can get it stuffed
with mozzarella, pepperoni,
jala-pee-nos.
Jala-pee-nos?
Jala-pee-nos.
How do you say it?
I'm messing with a Marine,
giving him a hard time about
how he says "jalapeño."
Put a little mozzarella
in there.
We basically take it
and just roll it.
For Valentine's Day, you know,
we make hearts.
You can make these in any shape
you want, but for you...
I made one of those.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
I'm creative.
[ Laughs ]
A little salt.
All right.
Throw it in the oven?
What temp?
450.
How long's that gonna take
to roll through?
About five minutes.
And here we go, coming out of
the oven, ready to plate it up.
A little
homemade marinara.
Where are you
gonna stick that?
When you think
about having a cold beer,
watching the game,
you want something like this.
You got any mustard?
Yeah, we do.
All right. See, this --
this is how you do it.
That's a pretzel.
You hand-make it, and you
serve it with some attitude.
That's right.
[ Chuckling ] You got it.
This is the floor show.
[ Chuckles ]
Gooey, cheesy delightfulness.
Hot cheese, hot bread --
can't go wrong with that.
You got anything else
up your sleeve, there, Marine?
Pot pie. Awesome.
The pot pie.
Legit?
Legit. Homemade.
Pot pie at a sports bar.
You want to see it
on "Triple D"?
Come back.
Hanging out with this guy.
Oof!
[ Laughs ]
Welcome back.
Having a great time hanging out
at Sidewinders
in Jackson, Wyoming.
This marine right there,
this aviator
has got his hands full
with a scratch-made joint
and a really cool sports bar.
And now we are going
chicken pot pie.
This is real deal because we're
taking it from roasted chicken
all the way through.
Absolutely.
You the man.
We have our own rub
for the chicken.
Thyme. Oregano.
Parsley.
Little celery salt.
Little mustard.
Bushberry pepper.
Cayenne.
Wow.
Little red chili flake.
And granulated garlic.
Mix all this together,
and then we just take
this mixture, just rub it on.
Getting some under the carpet
there, aren't you?
Yeah, under the carpet.
Over.
Now, we gonna let this
set up a little bit
before you cook it?
Yeah, we let this set for like
two hours in the walk-in.
Then in the oven at 350,
hour, hour and 15 minutes.
Bring it out.
Let it cool.
Then we take the skin off
and pull it.
Pull all the meet,
save the bones,
make the stock that lives
in the house that Joe built.
You got it.
Gosh, I like
the way you roll.
Now we're gonna make the filling
for the chicken pot pie.
We start
with some olive oil.
Some mirepoix.
White onions.
Fresh garlic.
Celery.
Carrots.
Sweating everybody down.
Then we take our white wine.
We bring this up
to a slight boil
and then just bring it down
to a slow roll
for about 20 minutes.
Then once they're translucent,
we'll add our mushrooms.
Let this sweat down
some more.
Salt. Pepper.
Basil.
Oregano.
Parsley. Cayenne.
There you go, buddy.
Stir that in,
and let it heat up.
Chicken stock?
We make
our own chicken stock.
Bring it up
to a slow boil.
And next up?
The roux.
Cowboy roux.
"Cowboy roux"?
That's what we call it.
'Cause we're
the Cowboy State.
I've never heard
anybody name their roux.
Kangaroo.
[roux]
Just mix that in, get
everything coated real nice.
I get nothing for that?
[ Crickets chirping ]
Heavy cream.
We'll mix that in again,
reduce it down about a third.
Potatoes.
Pulled chicken.
You stir that in and simmer this
for about 15 minutes.
Then she's ready to go.
Puff pastry on top.
Little egg wash.
Okay. In the oven,
and that's it?
That's it.
Six minutes.
Got it.
Look at that.
Good-looking pot pie.
You know, there's something
about chicken on the bone,
to make the stock
from the bone.
There's such a depth.
It's creamy. Love that you got
the mushrooms in there.
Not a ton of crust.
The veggies are tender,
but you get some real texture
out of those carrots
and the celery.
Dynamite.
Thanks.
Watch out for this guy.
RICE:
Chicken pot pie.
There's a lot of really tasty
things inside of it.
MAN: It's creamy, has a great
crunch on the crust up top.
It's hearty.
It's great.
This is a destination
restaurant. You do
want to come here.
Just a wonderful place to come.
You named the joint
Sidewinders
after something
that was so major in your life,
being a pilot
in the Marine Corps.
So I could understand why,
when you're gonna do something
to that degree,
you're gonna make sure
that the food has that
much respect, as well.
And you
really have shown that.
That's not typically
what you find in a sports bar.
Nice job, Joe.
Thank you.
Really nice job.
FIERI: Coming up...
Got a lot
to be proud of, girl.
...an Italian spot
in Monterey, California...
This is, without question,
one of the craziest minestrones
I've ever seen.
...that's taking pride
in staying homegrown.
That's the example of lasagna
like your mom used to make.
So, I'm here
in Monterey, California,
known for Cannery Row
and awesome seafood.
Well, I'm in the locals area,
I'm downtown,
to check out a joint
that the locals love --
an old-school
family-run Italian joint.
This is Rosine's.
Angel hair pasta.
We're down two or three times
every week.
This is
our favorite restaurant.
Chicken Parmesan.
I don't like it.
I love it.
It's better
than my Sicilian grandma's.
Wow. Someone's out
of the will.
FIERI: Authentic Italian's been
headlining this joint
since 1980,
when Chef Jim Culcasi's parents,
Jim and Rosine,
made it a family affair.
Everything is absolutely
amazing. I've never had
a bad meal here.
Lasagna.
And the lasagna, with the layers
of stuff, it's really nice.
Okay, let's
get into making this.
We are making our Jim's special
filling for our lasagna.
Your who?
Jim's special --
my father's name.
Did he make this, or your mom
made this for your dad?
My mom for my dad.
That's beautiful.
All right, fire it up, man.
All right.
We start off with olive oil.
Then we drop in
our ground chuck.
We're all browned up.
Next up?
Onions. Mushrooms.
Oregano.
Granulated garlic.
Sweet basil.
Touch of salt.
And pepper.
We let this cook.
and then we add the nutmeg.
And then the spinach.
All that is gonna work as
the layering inside the lasagna.
Yes.
Next up?
We're going to build
the lasagna.
Together.
We start off with our red sauce
on the bottom.
Pasta sheets.
And then go with ricotta.
Jim's special.
Next, Parmesan cheese.
Parm.
Jack cheese.
Jack?
Jack.
More sauce.
How many layers?
Four.
[ Whistles ]
Off in the oven
at what temp?
350 for an hour.
Bring it out, let it cool.
Let it cool.
There we go.
Sauce the top.
Little Parmesan cheese
and parsley.
There we go.
This has got
multiple layers.
Super rich and thick.
Tender pasta. Creamy.
All the balance.
That's the example of lasagna
like your mom used to make.
Jimbo, nice job, man.
Nice job. Mom did it right.
She sure did.
All right. Here you guys go.
Here's your lasagna.
It's like the perfect amount
of meat and cheese.
How's that lasagna?
It's as big as your head.
It is enormous,
and it is incredibly tasty.
Ultimate burger, reuben.
Table six!
How long you worked here?
All my life, basically.
Since 1980.
Your mom's place?
My mom's, Rosine.
Is your mom Italian?
Yes. Sicilian, actually.
FIERI:
And if you time it right,
you'll catch Rosine herself
helping out in the kitchen.
This is definitely a family.
You couldn't get any more family
than this.
They're always walking
around to make sure you
got everything you want.
You're gonna get
a wonderful home-cooked
meal, wonderful portion.
MAN:
Here's your minestrone.
Tell me
about the minestrone.
Minestrone's
off the charts.
The minestrone soup is
one of the locals' favorites.
We're gonna make
our minestrone soup.
Okay.
We start with top round.
Do we get hot?
No. We start it cold.
Watch.
I'm getting a little
freaked out right now, but
I'll with what you got.
Dry red beans.
Granulated garlic
and onion.
Hold on.
How many cups
of granulated onion and garlic?
A lot.
Sugar.
Oregano.
Sweet basil.
Black pepper.
Bay leaves.
White pepper.
Tomato paste.
Beef base.
Then we add water.
Okay.
We give it a stir.
Here we go.
And then we add our diced
tomatoes and our tomato sauce.
This is, without question,
one of the craziest minestrones
I've ever seen.
No other veggies.
No, no.
This is the first part.
This is the beginning.
Okay, don't rush the song.
We're gonna let this cook
for about four hours.
Four hours.
Now we're ready to pull out
all the beef.
Okay.
All right.
Just put it on the pan.
All the beef's out.
You let this cool down
before you shred it.
Exactly.
Next step will be,
we add celery.
Carrots.
Zucchini.
Onions.
And cabbage.
I like where this is
going. How much longer
you gonna let this cook?
Till the vegetables are tender.
About an hour.
There we go.
You take all this meat now,
shred it...
Shred it, yes.
...and throw it back in.
All right, Jimmy,
dish it up.
A little pasta in.
Okay.
So, I like the pasta's not
floating in the pot thing,
'cause that
always drives me nuts.
And then we top it off
with Parmesan cheese.
Start your meal.
I love the cabbage
in there.
The shredded beef,
not something you
typically find in minestrone.
A nice, rich broth.
I mean, the whole thing.
Great.
It's delicious. But I
want to call the real boss in.
Rosine,
are you back there?
Now, this
is the authority.
You got a lot
to be proud of, girl.
Very nice to meet you.
Well, thank you, Guy.
Look at her. To the nines --
the hair, the bling.
We have a rule
that you can't wear more bling
than the host of the show.
Oh, my gosh!
[ Laughs ]
JIM: Minestrone!
MAN: Can't wait
to get it in your mouth.
As soon as you taste it,
you know that it's
absolutely homemade.
MAN #2:
Here's your lamb shanks.
Young Man: It feels like home.
You get good, cooked food.
It's real hearty, fills you up.
Come down Friday.
That's when she's here
making the cakes.
Oh, I'll make you
a pie you won't forget.
FIERI: Up next,
in Boston, Massachusetts...
It's gonna be okay.
We're jumping together.
...a neighborhood joint
stuffing supper...
The bird is the word.
...into sandwiches.
Rock-star sandwich.
Delicious.
So, I'm here at Boston
in front of a "Triple D"
original -- Mike's City Diner.
All right, Jay,
what do you got for me?
You're in the wrong place.
Around the corner,
across the hospital.
Great gourmet sandwiches.
The bomb.
You the man.
Thanks.
This is it.
This is Blunch.
One beef ready to go.
Serving up sandwiches
has been job number one
for Chef Nikki Christo
since she opened up
this funky little space in '07.
How many square feet
you have here, 6?
Uh, no, 400.
400.
Here's the loaf.
WOMAN: I've pretty much had
everything on the menu,
and I've never had
a bad thing here.
Her concept?
Serving a great, savory dinner
between two slices of bread.
My favorite is meat loaf.
She makes her own roast beef.
The bird is probably my go-to
sandwich when I come here.
The first one we're making
is the bird.
Yep.
We're gonna start with boneless,
skinless chicken breast
with a little olive oil.
Dried basil.
Granulated garlic?
That's correct.
Black pepper.
A blend of Italian seasoning.
Granulated onion.
Little kosher salt.
A little bit of lemon juice
in here.
Finish it off with water.
Poaching the chicken.
Correct.
In the oven we go.
What temp?
375 degrees
for about 45 to 50 minutes --
until it reaches 165.
We chill overnight
so we get a better slice.
Give it a little slice.
There we go.
Little slice.
All right, so, now
we're gonna add some
of the artichoke aioli.
Next are
the oven-roasted tomatoes.
A little
mozzarella cheese.
We're gonna throw some of that
nice chicken in there.
Okay.
And now we're
gonna press her up.
Now we're gonna finish it
with some nice baby greens.
And that's the bird.
Don't hold your breath.
It's gonna be okay.
We're jumping together.
Okay.
Mmm.
Glad, you're eating it.
"Eating it"?!
Geez, I'm gonna devour it.
A great sandwich.
It's the roast chicken dinner
on really good bread.
It's all house-made.
That rocks.
Awesome.
The bird is the word.
Awesome job, Nikki.
I got two birds
ready to fly.
MAN: Let me tell you
a little bit about the bird.
The meat is like
a little slice of heaven.
The vegetables are fresh.
I love the roasted tomatoes.
It's pretty taste-ado.
Nikki knows everybody by name.
One meltdown for Claudia.
For you, Vincent.
I thought I was special
'cause she'd say, "Hi, Bob,"
and then I realized,
no, she knows everybody.
The Provencal for you, Bob.
When someone says "Blunch,"
the first thing that comes
to mind is a Provencal sandwich.
The Provencal is one
of the many vegetarian
sandwiches on the menu
which I am a sucker for.
We're gonna make
the Provencal.
Let's make it happen.
We're gonna add
the goat cheese
that we whip here with
a little bit of light cream.
Then we're gonna take
a fresh-basil pesto.
We also puree
our own kalamata olives
with some
extra virgin olive oil.
Fresh tomatoes.
Quartered artichoke hearts.
The oven-roasted tomatoes.
Pop it on the press.
We're gonna finish
with baby greens.
Personally --
I like the name --
I would have called this
"Hippie Picnic."
A Hippie Picnic.
It's the best name for
a sandwich in the world.
Look at that.
Mmm.
Oh, yeah.
That richness of the goat cheese
really carries a long way.
But then you have
the roasted tomatoes,
and you have the artichoke
hearts, which have
great texture to them.
The fresh tomatoes,
the brightness from that.
And then the key to it is having
that super-hot panini --
really delivers the crunch
on the outside
and the fresh greens
going into it.
It's outrageous. I mean, it's
really a delicious sandwich.
Mmm.
Two Provencals
coming up.
Every bite is just
like a kaleidoscope that
opens up in your mouth.
FIERI:
So, I see what happens.
You have one of the most
successful "Triple D"
joints ever in Boston,
and you come looking
for the owner, and
he's down here eating.
This is our boy,
Jay Hajj.
You're the one that sent me
down here to Blunch.
I got to tell you,
she's so creative.
The food is awesome.
MAN: Nikki makes it with love,
and it's just a whole experience
when you come here
to have a Blunch sandwich.
I look at "Provencal."
That doesn't say "Buy me."
I look at "Hippie Picnic."
Says, "I'm in it to win it."
CHRISTO: "Buy me."
Yeah.
Rock-star sandwich.
Delicious.
It's good. Thank you.
So, that's it for this
edition of "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
What are you gonna melt?
The Grue-ay.
[ Laughter ]