Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
...we're headed to
the Flavortown pool...
Ooh, that sounds nice.
...and diving into
some all-day dining...
Flavor jets just turned on.
...in Wilson, Wyoming...
Look at that.
Get after it.
...a down-home joint...
Ooh, you know the knuckles.
I like this one.
...stacking up
an early-morning classic.
That's gourmet
French toast.
In Monterey, California...
Hello.
...a chef living the fresh
and local life...
Nice job.
...pulling off a triple play
of pork.
Well, here at
the delicate Wild Plum,
don't think you're not getting
a chuck wagon portion.
And in Long Beach, California...
Hey!
...a gastro pub
mixing up the menu...
Oh, I'm sorry.
Back up the one.
...with some
off-the-hook creations.
Shut the front door.
Shut the front
and the back door.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in the great state
of Wyoming,
right on Highway 22,
about 6 or 7 miles west
of Jackson Hole.
I mean, everybody knows
about Jackson Hole, right?
So I'm here to check out this
family-run neighborhood joint
where they are
scratch making everything
for breakfast, lunch,
and dinner.
This is Nora's Fish Creek Inn.
Prime rib, baked potato!
A unique little log cabin.
There's a giant fish on the top.
It's a normal Joe place
that you feel comfortable,
and there's great food.
Blue cheese mushrooms, please!
I've been coming here
for 30-plus years,
watching Kat grow up here.
FRIERI: Working for her mother,
Nora Tygum,
who started the joint
back in '82,
now Kat's picking up
where mother left off.
I've modified a lot
of her recipes,
but a lot of them I keep
the same because it's Nora's.
The food here is excellent.
Any meal here, any day.
It's one of our favorite places
to have breakfast.
Biscuit and gravy
and the huevos rancheros.
The pancakes, the French toast.
Banana bread French toast!
It's fantastic.
Banana bread sourdough
whole-wheat French toast.
Wow!
Let's do this.
Brown sugar, white sugar,
and a pound of butter.
Cream this.
Look at that.
Get after it.
Now I'm gonna add the eggs,
a couple at a time, mix again.
Now I'll add my sourdough.
Flavor jets just turned on.
White flour,
whole-wheat flour,
salt, soda,
nutmeg, cinnamon.
Allspice.
Clove?
A little clove.
And some baking powder.
Correct.
Now we're going to add
the dry ingredients
to the wet ingredients,
and I'll mix this.
Then I mash up the bananas,
and then
I'll scoop them in.
And then you're going to put
the mixer back to --
Back to work.
A little
labor of love here.
I like to let it sit
for about 30 minutes.
Hit it
with a little Aqua Net.
Then I'm gonna pour it
in the pan.
325 for an hour?
Yep.
All right,
so, bread's cooled down now.
It's three slices,
50/50 margarine and butter,
dip it in my eggs.
Did we put any milk
in the egg?
Nope, just egg.
Put it on the flat top.
Look at that omelette you have
on the outside of that.
Plate this up.
Powdered sugar, walnuts,
and some blueberries.
Breakfast avalanche you got
going on over here.
That's gourmet
French toast.
The whole wheat,
the bananas,
I mean, the whole spice cabinet
jumped in this one.
I love the allspice
getting in there.
There's enough sweetness
in there,
and the natural sweetness
of the blueberries coming in.
That's lights out.
Nicely done.
Awesome.
Ooh, you know the knuckles.
I do.
I like this one.
[ Laughs ]
The banana bread
is just unbelievable.
I love it so much that I just
want to keep eating it.
You look out your window,
and you see the Teton Mountains
all around you.
You can't take it for granted
because it's just so beautiful.
We come here a lot during
the week, during lunches.
Dinner, I have stroganoff
or prime rib.
FRIERI: Or why not have both
at the same time?
Pick up, stroganoff!
You make your beef stroganoff
with prime rib?
Leftover prime rib.
So you'll serve this
for dinner.
You have your end trimmings,
your leftover prime rib,
then you'll take that,
slice that up,
and use that to make
the stroganoff.
Correct.
Got it.
All right,
let's get into it.
We're making the homemade
noodles for the beef stroganoff.
So, all-purpose flour.
A little salt, milk,
my eggs.
And some clarified butter.
Got it.
Mix it up with my hands,
and I'm gonna knead it
to a nice ball.
And then I'm gonna
flour my surface
so they don't
stick together.
Roll it out, cut it in half,
and roll it up.
Slice it.
Big, hearty noodles.
Unroll 'em,
kind of break 'em apart,
let 'em dry out a little bit
on this cookie sheet.
Okay,
so we bust all this out.
Okay, so now we're gonna make
the stroganoff.
Yes.
So, we got
the clarified butter.
Melting with my garlic,
mushrooms, onions.
Let this sauté up
a little bit.
I'll add my flour,
building a little roux.
Then I'm gonna add
the leftover prime rib,
half and half, tarragon,
cracked black pepper,
chicken stock, wine.
So, in the winter months,
when everybody's
freezing cold up here,
this has got to be a hit.
Yes.
What temperatures on
a daily basis in December?
Minus 28.
Your hair freezes.
That's what happened.
[ Laughter ]
Let that come to a boil.
I'm gonna drop my noodles.
Noodles have puffed up.
Here's what I dig.
Super creamy.
I love the tarragon
in there.
You get a ton of meat.
You get a nice, big, fat,
hand-rolled noodle.
So it used to be
just on Wednesdays, huh?
Yep.
I guess I'll have to put it
on the menu.
That's me working
for you guys.
Nice job, girl.
Excellent. Delicious.
WOMAN:
The beef stroganoff.
The best thing about it is the
mushroom sauce that's cooked in.
I really enjoy
the homemade noodles.
I mean, you don't get them
very often.
So, this is still
a locals joint?
Very much local.
You might change that.
It's not me.
You're the ones that said,
"Come here."
[ Laughter ]
FRIERI: Coming up,
in Long Beach, California...
Outstanding.
...a neighborhood spot getting
outrageous with octopi...
Look at that, huh?
That is it.
...and dangerous
with the whole hog.
He's off the tail.
So, I'm here
in my old stomping grounds,
Belmont Shore
in Long Beach, California.
Matter of fact,
I used to live on that street
right there, Nieto.
Now, listen, a lot has evolved
since I lived down here.
Tons of new restaurants
with lots of character
like this joint.
This is tavern on 2.
Tavern on 2 burger.
It's a great local spot,
a hidden gem.
[ Bell dings ]
Pick up, let's go!
Surprisingly upscale,
gastro pubby food.
Can't be beat.
FRIERI:
The gastro pub menu
is exactly what this hood
was missing
when owner Brian Clark
opened in 2011.
We were actually
the first guy
to do what
we're doing down here.
It was pretty sparse.
It was Super Mex, still one
of my favorite joints.
But there was no joint
like tavern on 2.
Right.
Throw in Chef Frank DeLoach,
who left behind fine dining
to show off his culinary skills,
and ink, here.
Let me get
some inventory here.
Very nice.
Ah, sick.
What type of food
do you guys do here?
Generally,
we try to take a lot
of influence
from the neighborhoods.
So, we have a lot
of Asian influence,
Mexican influence,
stuff like that.
Dig it.
Like this twist
on surf and turf.
MAN: Belly and sucker.
You've got octopus,
and you've got pork belly.
I mean, you can't go wrong.
Flavor that is just so unique
and so incredible.
What are we getting into?
We're gonna start off
with our pork belly
for our belly
and sucker dish.
Excellent.
So, salt and sugar,
top and bottom.
And we're gonna let this brine
for how long?
Typically,
we do this overnight.
Okay.
Beer and water.
Braise it at 300 degrees
until nice and tender.
Next up.
Octopus.
Yes. Look at this.
We're gonna go
in the pot.
We're gonna braise it
with a little bit of water,
red wine vinegar,
some salt,
black peppercorns, bay leafs,
whole garlic.
And how long
are we gonna let this go?
For about four hours.
Low and slow?
Low and slow.
Bring it out, let it cool.
Overnight,
in its own liquid.
Okay, Chef, we ready?
Ready.
So now the belly's out,
we're gonna press it.
There we go.
And we're gonna take
our other sheet tray,
lay it right on top,
and we add a little bit
of weight.
And why are we
gonna weigh it?
Try to get a nice, uniform
texture so we slice it later.
You don't have
all these gaps.
Then we're
gonna go overnight.
Got it.
What goes
on the top of this?
A black currant
vinaigrette.
Ooh, that sounds nice.
So, we have just
some dried black currants,
diced shallots,
season everything up
with a nice pinch of salt,
then we add
our red wine vinegar,
equal parts to burgundy.
Quite a few grounds
of black pepper.
About a full
two tablespoons.
We're gonna let this go until
all the currants are plump,
so about four to five minutes
on full, rapid boil.
Then it's ready to roll.
Excellent.
So we have our octopus.
Beautiful, okay.
It's so tender,
we can just pull it apart.
I like it.
This is the pork belly
we've been pressing overnight.
Portion it into about
the width we want first.
And just slice it up.
Beautiful.
Cold pan,
'cause we want to try
to really get it as crispy
as possible.
Let it come up to temp,
let it start to slowly render
by the time it starts
to cook off the fat.
GBD -- golden, brown,
and delicious.
Okay, so we let that go.
What are we gonna do
with the octopus?
We're actually gonna crisp
the octopus in a different way.
We're gonna fry it.
Refrying it just gets the best
texture all around.
Nice little crunch
on the outside.
Warm through the middle?
Absolutely.
We're now gonna take
carrot caramel.
With brown sugar?
Just carrot.
Just a carrot reduction?
That's it.
Lay this guy in a bowl.
It's got nice GBD?
Yes, it does have nice GBD.
We then have
our very crispy octopus.
Yes, we do.
We're gonna go real crazy
with it.
Look at that, huh?
That's half the fun.
That is it.
Red radishes, jicama.
A little bitterness,
a little crunch.
A little bit
of the vinaigrette,
some of those currants,
dill, fennel, cilantro,
chervil, nasturtium.
Wait, I'm sorry,
back up the one.
Nasturtium.
Nasturium?
As the flower.
You know, I just ran out
of nasturtium earlier today.
All right, the belly is
ridiculous, fall apart.
It is so unctuous.
It's pretty rich.
Oh!
I am a humongous
octopus fan.
And this is simple,
but incredibly flavorful
and refined.
You know what the real kicker
of it is?
Is the freshness of the veg,
the herbs,
the brightness
that those bring.
Shut the front door.
Shut the front
and the back door.
It's that good.
Dude,
you have mad skills.
Thank you.
Outstanding.
The tenderness of the octopus
combined with the pork belly
is just like nothing else.
WOMAN:
There's a lot of interesting
food items on the menu
that I've never had before.
It's not like any place else.
I just feel that there is
something else
that you have
that I've got to try.
Pig tails.
Oh!
Don't go anywhere.
"Triple D" is hanging out
at Belmont Shores
in Long Beach, California.
When we come back, the wild man
brings the pig tails.
See you in a bit.
Welcome back.
We're at tavern on 2,
the Belmont Shore,
Long Beach, California,
my old stomping grounds,
and we have had the belly
and sucker, outrageous.
And now, after all of this,
you're gonna give me pig tails.
Pig tails.
It's like
pork chicken wings.
Pork chicken wings.
Okay.
They look kind of strange.
Yes, they do.
I was kind of expecting
to be a little --
Everyone does.
So we're not even gonna touch
those or mess around with them.
We're just gonna put 'em
right in there.
Everybody in the pool.
Salt, sugar.
Okay.
Coriander, black pepper,
red onions.
Dig it.
Cilantro stems,
just a few.
Got it, only need
two or six handfuls.
Ginger.
And Mary Ann.
Little bit of water.
Rice wine vinegar.
We're gonna let these simmer
for about three hours,
lay 'em onto a sheet tray,
and let 'em cool overnight.
They congealed inside of
their own braising liquid now.
We're gonna take 'em off
and portion 'em.
And so --
They're that soft, you can just
pop right through 'em.
Now we're gonna
deep fry 'em.
We're gonna let them go
for about four minutes.
Got it.
Until GBD.
Until they're GBD.
While the tails
are bopping --
We're gonna add the sauce.
Got it.
Hoisin, oyster sauce,
sambo,
black bean sauce, o.j.,
lime juice,
water, sriracha,
brown sugar.
Very nice.
A few of
my favorite things.
I enjoy.
So we got our nice
crispy fried tails.
We're gonna get 'em
in a sauce.
This is where it becomes
sticky pig tails.
Sticky pig tails.
Everything's better
when it's sticky.
Back on a vinyl car seat,
not so much.
Roasted sesame seeds,
scallions.
So, nice,
sticky pig tails.
Almost like Chinese
takeout style.
I like it.
It's a big wing.
It's exactly what it is.
Some micro cilantro, a little
more sesame raw, and scallions.
It's like a pork rib
that really had a chance
to cook down a little bit.
Great texture to it...
nice meatiness.
And when you offer things as
eclectic as pig tails fried up,
toss in an awesome
spicy Asian sauce...
I don't know what to say.
You rock, man.
Thank you, sir.
Go get 'em.
Pig tails, pick up!
MAN: The pig tails blow
chicken wings out of the water.
The sweet and savory sauce
that's on there
is just incredible,
and the meat, it's so tender.
WOMAN: They're sticky,
and you need
a wet nap when you're done.
They're wonderful.
Have you ever had
a pig tail before?
Not before here.
I mean,
the flavor is banging.
WOMAN:
I love tavern on 2.
It's casual.
People are really friendly.
The food is sensational.
Food's off the hook.
Dude's off the tail.
Hey!
FRIERI: Up next...
You make your rubs.
You make your sauces.
...in Monterey, California...
You make your bread,
you make your muffin.
...the local joint running
a scratch-made marathon.
You make your --
Everything.
Except the ketchup
and mustard.
So, I'm here in the old town
of Monterey, California,
to check out a joint.
Now, get this.
They have people growing
their produce for 'em.
They're baking
just about everything.
They're into sustainability
and total organics,
and get this.
They scratch make everything
except the ketchup and mustard.
This is the Wild Plum.
Some of the best food
on the Monterey peninsula.
WOMAN:
Basil burger, table six.
Best of a farmer's market
on a plate.
This is a salad bowl
of the whole country,
and Pamela is so good
about making sure
she incorporates
local fresh vegetables.
FRIERI: A code Chef Pamela Burns
has pretty much lived by
since she opened this place
back in '99.
She's like the hippie auntie
I always wanted.
I don't even want to
call it homemade
because I could never make
anything like this at home.
WOMAN:
Pickup, please, porchetta!
I mean, it's pork and bacon.
Where can you go wrong?
And the way the flavors
bounce in your mouth,
it's just phenomenal.
Porchetta -- I don't see
the big belly and the --
I'm not doing it that way.
I'm doing a version
of porchetta.
Oh, hello.
Is that all right?
Oh, yeah,
this is your house, girl.
You have the knife, also.
That's right.
I make a pork filling
with roasted pork shoulder.
So we're gonna cut this down,
keeping this up.
Season with salt and pepper,
extra virgin olive oil.
And we're gonna go
with our bacon fat,
brown sugar,
onions, fennel.
Whole garlic,
chopped oregano.
Roast it for an hour.
And then we add apples
to it,
and then another
hour and a half, two hours.
Now we work
with the pork loin.
I'm gonna butterfly this.
So I'm gonna go like this.
Getting medieval on it,
aren't you?
I'm gonna stuff it
with some garlic.
I'll slice, you put.
All right, perfect.
Okay, now we're in there.
Salt, pepper, olive oil --
just a smidge.
Rub that in there.
A little blend of oregano
and thyme.
And then we do the same thing
to the other side.
Now I'm gonna give this
a little shot of brown sugar.
On both sides.
Okay?
Now we're ready to roll.
Pork filling,
and we're gonna do
a pinwheel roll.
Okay, so here we go.
Give it a good roll
like that.
I tie this so that it will
stay together,
and then I do the bacon
just like this on top.
You lay the bacon on top?
I lay the bacon on top.
You tie it off,
and then you tie it again?
I tie it again.
Now it's ready to roast.
At approximately 350
for about 40 minutes.
And I cook it
a little bit rare
'cause I'm gonna sear it
on one side.
Because I just don't want
the pork to be dry.
Nothing worse.
Let me just
pick that off there.
Sure. [ Laughs ]
That came out
pretty perfect.
Gorgeous.
Yeah.
A little bit of olive oil.
Let that sit
for like one minute.
Now flip it.
Put in my apples
and my pears.
Just a pinch of salt,
and I'm just gonna pour
a little bit of this juice
that we've strained off
the roasted pork filling,
and then I finish it in the oven
for like four or five minutes.
We ready?
Yep!
Pan-fried potatoes.
A whole bunch of 'em.
And then I'm gonna
put in the pork.
A little bit
of the good stuff.
Here at
the delicate Wild Plum,
don't think you're not getting
a chuck wagon portion.
All right.
What I love
about porchetta
is that you get all the
different parts of the pig.
You get the salty,
crunchy bacon side of it.
Here, you've incorporated
the shoulder,
which has tremendous flavor,
and wrapping the bacon
around the outside.
The loin gets
all that flavor,
more flavor in the loin
than it has.
Right.
Adding the pear
and the apple,
it's just such an elevated
flavor profile,
and it gives it
such balance.
Really neat.
Oh, thank you.
Good job.
Wow, this is just like
this huge piece of bacon.
Just smoky and sweet.
It is just absolutely wonderful.
MAN:
Really well cooked.
Worth seeking out.
WOMAN: Everything that she puts
her hand to
is always just
very, very special.
WOMAN #2:
Sage sausage skillet.
I love her baked goods.
Whether it's her muffins,
her scones, her pies.
You make your batters,
you make your rubs,
you make your sausage,
you make your bread,
you make your muffins.
That's right.
Everything.
Except the ketchup
and mustard.
Nice job.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
What is this?
Belly and sucker.
We're belly and sucker.
[ Laughs ]
Which one am I?
You're definitely belly.
Damn!
[ Both laugh ]