Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Look at this.
...we're seeking out
the standards...
Yes!
...that totally stand out.
Knock your mama
out the rocking chair.
We don't typically use
that line on "Triple D."
FIERI: In Jackson, Wyoming,
rock-star Mexican...
There were sopes
at the bottom of this.
...with high-altitude attitude.
This would be outstanding
in California.
This is remarkable
all the way out here.
Then in Long Beach,
California...
I'm a brain surgeon.
I just do it through
their belly.
...a colorful bistro
serving up local food...
It's a huge hit.
It's really delicious.
...with artistic flair.
You're painting
your own masterpieces.
And in Carmel, California...
Calm down, G.
You're dancing.
Ooh!
FIERI:
...tag-teaming with G. Garvin
on some righteous
East Coast Italian.
Just a bada, no bing.
FIERI: My man.
Three words.
Forget about it.
Ooh.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here
in this cool little town
called Carmel-by-the-Sea,
California.
Great restaurants,
lots of cool little shops,
and I'm hanging out
with my buddy here,
G. Garvin
from The Cooking Channel.
Now, G., I know
what you're wanting.
You're saying, "Get me some
really good barbecue sauce,
some sweet potatoes --"
Oh! No barbecue.
Then how about Italian?
This is Little Napoli.
Ravioli going down
with the Arrabbiata sauce.
WOMAN: It's so good.
And I just know
that I'm getting
something authentic.
PèPE:
Chicken parmigiana, here we go.
It just embraces everything
that Italian life
is supposed to be.
FIERI: That's because since
1989, owner and chef Rich Pèpe
has been serving up
family recipes
you don't usually see
outside the boot.
A lot of people
don't understand
how regional
Italian food is.
With all my grandparents
coming from Southern Italy,
that's where
we really focus.
That's what I grew up with.
And also, being from
New Jersey, you know,
if you don't put good food
on the table,
somebody's gonna get hurt.
Truly.
[ Laughter ]
PèPE:
Cannelloni tricolore, pick up.
Love the cannelloni.
It's such a surprise
when it arrives.
It has red, white, and green
like the Italian flag.
Tricolore.
Three colors, my brother.
Come on!
My man.
So, how we starting
this off?
Working the stuffing
right now?
Yes, sir.
Hit it.
Pèppoli extra virgin
olive oil,
onions, zucchini,
yellow squash, and mushrooms.
Fresh ground pepper
over the top.
Little bit of kosher salt.
So, we're just gonna
cook that down
for just a couple
of moments.
Just sweating it a bit.
Just sweating it a bit
'cause it will cook later on
when we make
the cannelloni roll.
Chicken coming in.
This is grilled chicken.
Okay.
Just a little parsley
at the end just to fold.
Basically, that's done.
Now we're gonna make
the pesto sauce.
Got it.
Garlic.
Fresh basil.
A lot of it.
Olive oil.
Parmigiano-reggiano.
Blend it just
for a couple of seconds.
I don't want to heat
that cheese up at all.
I like you leave a little
texture to it. Okay.
Let me get after that
for you, boss.
[ Chuckles ]
Nice, G.
Hey, man.
I'm over here helping.
G.'s digging
in the back side.
Hey, I'm a guest
on the show, baby.
I get to do what I want to do.
Okay. Now we'll fold in
a little heavy cream.
Now you make your own pasta,
as well.
We do.
Wow.
Just a traditional...
semolina and egg pasta.
And one, two, three.
Then go and boil it off,
little salt water.
So, this is our
pre-boiled sheet.
Pipe in the ricotta
and parmesan and egg
filling cheese.
Bada bing.
Did we just get
a "bada bing"?
You got
a little bada bing.
Bada who?
A little shout out for Jersey.
What can I say?
Now we can take
our filling.
We're gonna lay it
across.
We did let it cool down
just a little bit.
Now we are just gonna
fold it over,
making like a big burrito.
We'll cut this whole piece
in three.
Now we're gonna go
into the skillet
with a little bit of water
and we're gonna steam it up.
Two, three minutes.
Two or three minutes.
Just a bada, no bing.
Then we're gonna plate
this puppy up.
Now I'm gonna come in
with our three sauces.
The marinara.
Pesto cream sauce.
And the Alfredo.
Shaved
reggiano parmigiano.
Roasted pine nuts.
Pea shoots.
I got to tell you.
Just like the Italian flag.
It is gorgeous.
We'll meet in the middle
like "Lady and the Tramp."
Whoa.
[ Chuckles ]
Calm down, G.
You're dancing.
Man.
Here we go.
Get it out.
Three words.
Forget about it.
Ooh.
That's the best compliment
you can get.
To me,
one of the keys to this
that I'm really digging
is the simplicity.
You execute the pasta perfectly,
you make your own sauces.
But what makes the dish
so great
is with so many flavors
on the plate,
there's no reason to make it
any more complex.
Just let the simplicity of it
shine through.
And that's really
what I enjoy the most.
Man, it all works well together.
It's phenomenal.
Nice job, Pèpe.
Thank you.
Excellent.
Tricolore cannelloni.
Everything inside's very warm
and fresh and delicious.
Everything tastes fabulous
from the very beginning
until the very end.
Cioppino rosso.
Okay.
Next up, what do we got?
We're coming in now
with the cioppino rosso.
Ohh!
I'm ready.
So, here's the deal.
We're hanging out
at Little Napoli
in Carmel, California,
on "Triple D"
with Chef Pèpe,
my man the G. Garvin.
See you in a minute.
FIERI: Welcome back.
Guy Fieri hanging out here
at "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives"
with my buddy G. Garvin
and we are at Little Napoli
with Chef Pèpe,
and we just had some cannelloni
that would, what?
Ooh, knock your mama
out the rocking chair.
Knock your mama
out the rock--
We don't typically use
that line on "Triple D."
Chef Pèpe,
we're gonna make cioppino.
This is bouillabaisse
gone wild.
We're gonna make the sauce
and we're gonna use the shells.
So I'm really just going
to just rub some paste
through the shells
and just put them in the oven
for about 15 minutes
just to get them warmed up.
350 degrees?
Yeah, maybe 350.
Great.
In a warm stock pot,
extra virgin olive oil.
Some red onion.
Chopped garlic.
Lots of it.
Chopped celery.
Carrots.
Saffron threads.
Nice.
Color and flavor.
All right, Chef.
You can see we've just kind
of caramelized the shells a bit,
roasted the tomato paste
on there.
Stir it up a little bit,
bring them all...
Deglaze
with some white wine.
Come in
with some ground tomatoes.
Crushed red pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Oregano.
Fair amount of salt.
Good little stir.
How long
do you let it cook for?
Top on, we got
about 15, 20 minutes.
Pull it, strain it.
Exactly.
And we use the immersion blender
on it.
Cioppino sauce is done.
The bada bing.
He says "bada bing"
one more time,
I'm gonna kick him out
of the rocking chair.
[ Whispering ]
The bada bing.
Now we're putting it
together.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Shallot.
Manila clams.
Black mussels.
Calamari.
White prawns.
Scallops.
Calamari tentacles.
Crab claw.
Baby shrimp.
Stir it up a little bit.
Deglaze with white wine,
Chardonnay.
Reduce it down.
Cioppino sauce
that we made earlier
coming right over the top.
And as soon as that's hot
and those clams open,
we're good to go.
We're done.
Cover it up.
2, 3, 4 minutes,
you're finished.
Got it.
Fresh pasta going down
in the boiling water.
Let's take a look
at our cioppino.
Mmm, it's gorgeous.
Pasta coming out
of the water.
Oh!
Look at that.
A little sauce
over the top.
And now we are gonna go in
with our seafood.
Look at this.
Right over the top.
That's like grandma
used to make.
Fresh parsley over the top.
Little chili oil
over the top.
Ohh.
I don't want to hurt you.
I don't want to hurt you now.
Cioppino rosso.
You make the pasta,
you make the sauce,
you roast the shells,
you live in the house
of Pèpeville.
Oh, the sauce is bananas.
Nice spice to it.
Pasta's not overcooked.
This is spicy, just the right
amount of heat.
It's gorgeous.
Oh, it's spot-on.
I make cioppino.
It's one of my favorite
personal dishes.
This is outstanding.
Oh, yeah.
That means a lot.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Okay.
Now I'm done.
Cioppino rosso.
Andiamo.
WOMAN: It makes you feel like
you're in the Italian coast
with fresh seafood that
just jumps out of the water.
MAN:
It's pretty much the only place
that we can come and get it
where it's very similar
to how we make it at home.
Pèpe knows exactly
what he's doing.
Little bit of shallots.
What you've done,
how you're doing it,
you're a lover
of the Italian culture,
and you really exude that.
Wonderful.
Very nice to meet you,
Chef.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Jackson, Wyoming...
I can't shovel this in
fast enough.
...Mexican-made
with old-school style.
This is the only one in Jackson.
I'm pretty sure of it.
That's gangster.
So, I'm here
in Jackson, Wyoming,
and I'm about two miles
from the center of town
over in kind of
the locals' area.
Now, when you think of Jackson,
what do you think of?
Well, of course, outdoor sports.
But when it comes to food,
what kind of food?
Well, one of the first that
would come up is wild game.
Then you'd have
some steakhouses.
But do you think
of Mexican food?
Well, you don't
until you try this joint.
This is Pica's.
MAN:
Marinated shrimp tacos.
You can tell
that what they're making,
they're making because
they love what they're doing.
Chicken mole plate.
You know, it's like
when you go down to Mexico
and someone fixes you a dish
in a place you'd never expect.
That's what you get here.
FIERI: That someone is chef
and owner Andy Parazette,
a So-Cal dude
who left behind the surf
to open up this mountain
taqueria in 2001.
Were you always
in the restaurant business?
After college,
I started cooking
and learned
different dishes
from different parts
of Mexico.
Tinga sopes up.
The sopes are so homemade.
They're delicious.
What are you gonna make us?
We're gonna make
tinga chicken sopes.
Tinga?
What's tinga?
That's a traditional
Mexican type of chicken.
Get going.
I'm starving.
All right.
So, this is the dried masa,
salt, water.
There you go.
Done.
Good.
This is about
as old-school real deal --
where did this one
come from?
Down in Mexico.
This is the only one in Jackson.
I'm pretty sure of it.
That's gangster.
Now we're gonna roll the masa
into balls.
Over the plastic.
You don't press it
too hard.
You want to keep them
a little thick.
All right.
So, you take it.
FIERI:
And when we make the sope,
especially with
this tinga chicken,
it's gonna have
some moisture to it.
So this kind of gives it
a little well to sit in.
Yeah.
Okay. Let's go.
Now we make
the chicken tinga.
Hit it.
Canola oil.
Heat up julienned onions.
FIERI: So, the onions
are caramelized.
Now the chicken?
The chicken.
And you pour
the tinga salsa.
Tinga salsa has
guajillo chillies,
Morita chillies,
fresh tomatoes, and beer.
Dried Mexican oregano.
So, cook this down,
let the chicken absorb
all of this great flavor.
We cook it
for about 30 minutes.
Okay, brother.
Chicken tinga is done.
Sopes down.
You just put a little fry
on these.
They'll still be tender.
If you've never had
a sope before,
you have got to try them.
One of my favorite things.
What kind of beans
are we using?
We're using refried beans.
Okay.
With lard?
With lard.
Yes!
Our chicken tinga.
Romaine lettuce,
white onion.
There were sopes at the bottom
of this earlier.
Tomato.
Chipotle salsa.
Mexican cheese.
Sour cream.
It's outrageous.
I can't shovel this in
fast enough.
The sauce fits.
The sopes got a little crunch.
Nice and thin.
Holds together well.
Mmm.
Outstanding.
All right.
MAN: Well, the chicken
is super tender,
kind of falls apart
when you bite it.
The sauces are amazing.
I love the sauces.
Everybody in town
comes to Pica's.
This is the place to go.
Here are your tacos al pastor.
You get kind of a melting pot
here of folks,
you know, that come
to Jackson Hole.
We get people from Texas,
New Mexico, California.
All those different people
have different ideas
of what --
Different expectations.
...Mexican food is, yeah.
We're from Ecuador.
What do you think
of this food?
I come to this place
two to three times a week.
My whole family likes it.
I bring my kids here.
Posole verde.
Posole, for me, is
a comfort food, you know?
WOMAN:
It's extremely fresh.
The cabbage, the pork,
everything is just --
it's amazing.
So, we're gonna do
the pork posole verde.
And so, what we have here
is fresh tomatillos
and jalapeños.
Next we take water
and fill it.
They're gonna cook
for about 25 minutes.
We're gonna take a sauté pan
and take julienned onions
and garlic.
And let that just sit
and caramelize down.
Yep.
So, we're gonna strain this.
And then we'll puree them.
Yes.
And then we add
a little cumin.
Ground cumin.
Let 'er rip.
So, now we're gonna take
the blended-up tomatillo
and jalapeños and refry it
in the pot.
Then we're gonna add
the chicken stock
and our salt and pepper.
While that's cooking,
I'm gonna cut up our pork.
And we're gonna cook it
in this pan with what?
Yellow onion and garlic.
And cook that
for about 45 minutes.
All right.
Pork's ready to go.
PARAZETTE:
Everybody in the pool.
Big splash.
And our hominy.
And we let it cook for
another 20 to 30 minutes.
All right.
So, fresh cabbage.
Fresh onion.
Mexican cheese.
Fresh cilantro.
Twist of lime.
And the fried tortilla.
Got a little Valentina
hot sauce?
Mm.
And not that this needs
hot sauce,
but there's just something about
all the times I've had posole
that I got to have
a little bit of that tang.
It's the freshness
of the cilantro
and the crunch of the onion
and the cabbage.
And the pork is ridiculous,
fall-apart tender.
Mmm!
Snap!
There's your posole verde.
It's kind of addicting.
The spicy
with the sweet and tangy.
When you live in a destination
resort like Jackson Hole,
one of the places you always
recommend is Pica's.
And I'm gonna tell you
something, man.
This would be outstanding
in California.
This is remarkable
all the way out here.
Great job.
Thanks a lot.
FIERI: Up next, an artist/chef
in Long Beach, California...
Au jus!
...working
her culinary canvas...
That's a rock-star dish.
Nice job, girl.
...with a full rainbow
of flavors.
Ladies and gentlemen,
give it up for the chef.
So, I'm here on Atlantic Avenue
in Long Beach, California,
in the Bixby Knolls neighborhood
to check out a joint
where the chef/artist
is painting her creativity
on the canvas and the plate.
This is The Factory Gastrobar.
Au jus!
Presentation is great.
The ingredients are different.
The menu changes constantly.
Spanish fish tacos
in the window.
Self-taught chef and owner
Natalie Gutenkauf
opened this comfort-food joint
in 2009,
combining her two loves --
art and food.
Order up!
This is all
you've wanted to do,
be in
the restaurant business?
No.
Okay.
I wanted to be a brain surgeon.
[ Laughs ]
Awesome.
Aren't we all?
I'm a brain surgeon.
I just do it through
their belly.
Exactly.
Asparagus sandwich!
Order up!
WOMAN:
It's a wonderful combination
of fresh asparagus,
arugula, tomato.
Absolutely amazing.
It's so delicious.
What's the first thing
we're gonna work on?
A white-bean hummus.
These are already
cooked-off white beans.
Got it.
Whole garlic.
A bunch of it.
Fresh basil.
Next is some fresh-squeezed
lemon juice.
And a little S and P.
All right.
Get this baby on here.
We're gonna add
a little bit of olive oil.
So, that's done.
What's next?
We're gonna make
the sandwich.
Awesome.
Asparagus.
Got it.
Little salt and pepper.
And...can you guess
what this oil?
Hop oil.
Fantastic.
It is.
I love hops.
So, all it is,
is olive oil, hops,
little bit of lemon rinds.
Kind of get it
juiced up there.
Put it on the grill.
Let it sit there
for a couple minutes.
A nice thick slice
of red onion.
Great.
This is ciabatta bread.
Just get a little grill marks
on it.
Arugula.
Little spoonful
of the dressing.
Get that mixed in.
We've got our ciabatta
grilled up here.
White bean
and basil hummus.
Baby arugula salad.
Grilled onion on here.
And our asparagus.
A little
yellow tomatoes here.
Fresno chilies.
Roasted red bell pepper.
And hop oil.
Hop over there.
That is gorgeous.
[ Chuckles ]
From the crunchiness
of the bread
to the garlic in the hummus
to the asparagus
and to the char of the onion,
the notes go on
and on and on.
It's a huge hit.
It's really delicious.
It's beautiful.
It's balanced.
That's a rock-star dish.
Nice job, girl.
I've had great
vegetarian sandwiches.
But I got to say
that this is up in the top.
This is by far --
yes, I agree.
It's very refreshing.
The crisp arugula, the yellow
tomatoes -- it's a smash.
It is.
It really is.
WOMAN: Always fresh and
you can taste the difference.
That's one of the things I love
about The Factory.
How'd you come up
with the name?
It's after Andy Warhol's factory
in New York.
And they created
an art scene.
And I kind of have
that same concept here,
but it's a food scene.
It's art on a plate.
Plating the pig and grits.
MAN: You got the pork going on.
You got some capers.
You got onions.
You got carrots.
The pig and grits lines your
stomach with some good loving.
Beautiful pork butt.
Seasoned with a little bit
of salt and pepper.
We just want to brown it up.
Hear a sizzle.
We're good.
All right.
So we're seared on both sides?
We're gonna add some onions,
garlic, and the best part.
Now, this is an amber ale.
You're gonna pour that hot fat
on top of that?
Absolutely.
You want to get every bit
of the flavor in here.
This is gonna go
in the oven.
What temp?
About 250.
And it's gonna cook
for about three to four hours.
Okay.
What's next?
We need to do the grits.
Scoop some of this
pork au jus in here.
Nice.
This is
Hepp's alderwood salt.
Get a real nice
smoky flavor.
And we're gonna put it
into our boat here.
Next, we're gonna get
some pork out.
Candied carrots.
And blackened tomatoes.
And we're gonna put a dollop
of chimichurri sauce.
These are capers,
big capers.
[ Whistles ]
Dried figs.
Cilantro.
Ta-da!
La-ba!
Wow, there's a lot
going on.
When you get that bite
of the grits with the salt,
the chimichurri, and
that beer-roasted pork,
it really has all the depth
that you need.
It's really dynamite.
Fire, fire!
Pork is just slow-cooked.
It just falls apart.
This is very distinctive
and unique.
There is nothing else
in this area like it.
You're painting your own
masterpieces and it's unique.
Ladies and gentlemen,
give it up for the chef.
[ Applause ]
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Just so you know,
the show was over, like,
five minutes ago,
but we are continuing
to mow this down.
"Triple D" after hours.
Behind the scenes.
Mmm!