Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Awesome.
...we're hitting up
small-town standouts...
No, we're not.
Yes.
...serving up big-time flavor.
Is this the family plan?
In Parkland, Wisconsin...
You're a gangster.
...a funky country bar...
Feel like
I'm in "Roadhouse."
Patrick Swayze's
gonna ride up.
...that's got me working
on my posture.
How is one
going to enjoy this?
The stance.
Oh, you know the hunch?
In Jackson, Wyoming...
Keow!
...an eclectic spot
going au natural...
Be here all week.
Try the tempeh.
...when it comes to dressing
their dishes up right.
Off the hook!
And in Lancaster, Oregon...
Bo and Luke Duke
come by often?
...a kitchen
in a converted car carrier...
Close to a cup of cheese in
this abuse -- I mean this dish.
...called extreme for a reason.
We've seen some crazy stuff
on "Triple D."
This is up there.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in the northwest
corner of Wisconsin
about 20 minutes southeast
of Duluth, Minnesota.
[ Plane roars ]
Got some buddies stopping by.
Anyhow, I'm in the little town
of Parkland.
They got a post office, a town
hall, and a county courthouse,
but not the kind
of county courthouse
that's serving up sentences.
Nope. These folks are serving up
a menu you wouldn't expect.
This is The Kounty Quarthouse.
Back bacon and cheese
in the window.
[ Bell dings ]
It's a five-star dive bar.
WOMAN: This is The Kounty
Quarthouse, and you are served.
Judge Beth,
she does a wonderful job.
FIERI:
That would be Beth Cherny,
who spent 25 years catering
in Duluth
before picking up
this country joint in '06.
I bought it, and it was
a little rough-and-tumble bar.
It was?
Was.
I feel like
I'm in "Roadhouse."
Patrick Swayze's
gonna ride up.
When you start, you know,
transitioning this place
into great food,
what did people say?
"Thank God."
Really?
Pork and sweet potato pie
in the window.
It's a place that opens up
your taste buds
and gets you to try
some different things.
They bring out big foods
and big flavors.
Chipotle brisket
in the window.
I've had the chipotle brisket.
It's all amazing.
It's almost like
a pot roast sandwich.
What are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
our chipotle brisket.
We're gonna put onions
in the hotel pan.
Lay that right on top.
And then we're gonna use
some Wisconsin amber beer
for a braising liquid.
Garlic, pepper, salt.
Then we're just
gonna cover it.
That's all she wrote.
Yep.
6 hours at 350 degrees.
And we're gonna start
with our cheddar biscuits.
Give me the rundown.
We're gonna start with
some all-purpose flour.
Baking soda, baking powder.
Salt.
And we're gonna add
cold butter.
Let that go
for a little bit.
Till we got gravel.
Yep.
And then we're gonna add
some cheddar cheese.
Buttermilk.
Okay.
Now we're gonna put it
in a sheet pan.
You're just gonna bake it off
as one big biscuit?
One big biscuit.
No, we're not.
You're a gangster.
We're gonna brush it
with some butter.
Yes.
Put it in the oven,
and how long?
For about 45 minutes
at about 375 degrees.
There's our biscuits.
Then we just cut them
into 15.
I like this as just
one big biscuit monster.
Brisket's cooled,
and we're gonna get
into making the chipotle
madness of this whole gig.
Yes.
Add a little vegetable oil,
diced onion,
and some minced jalapeño.
Holy jalapeño, Batman.
It's pretty spicy.
Now we're gonna add a little bit
of chipotle peppers.
In adobo.
In adobo, and we just cook
for about a minute or two.
Now we're gonna work
with our brisket.
So, we're gonna get rid
of some of this fat.
Not much.
Then against the grain,
we're gonna cut it
in about one-inch strips.
Okay. Now we're gonna just chop
and pull with the knife.
I don't like
to over-shred it.
Kind of pot roasty.
You pot roastied it good,
though. I like it with the beer.
Now we're just gonna put this
in the bowl.
Before I eat it all.
Mmm.
We're gonna add a little
granulated garlic, salt,
smoked paprika,
and a little black pepper.
And then we're gonna add
that chipotle sauce to this.
We're pouring that on top.
Yep.
This all
gets mixed together?
Right.
Okay, now we're just
gonna make our sandwich.
Gonna take
a little bit brisket.
Heat that up.
And then we're gonna add
some caramelized onion.
Slice
of white cheddar cheese.
And then we're gonna just
pop it in the oven.
Just
until the cheese melts.
About two minutes.
Brisket.
Look at that tender,
cheesy biscuit.
We're just
gonna slice it.
Add a little bit
of clarified butter.
That's just
what that needed.
Hot meat on the biscuit.
We want those juices
on there, too.
Chipotle guacamole sauce.
And that's a chipotle
brisket sandwich.
That's ridiculous.
The brisket's
cooked perfectly.
Not too salty.
Got good fat,
but not too much of it.
That biscuit screams
for anything that you want
to put on it.
You got a nice little burn
from the jalapeño.
Cools it off
with the chipotle crema.
And enough
for seven people.
But delivered with
the culinary techniques
that you put to it,
spot on.
All right.
Chipotle brisket.
Brisket's amazing.
It's got a little sweet smokey.
Cheddar brisket.
Oh, melts in your mouth.
It's fun to have
this kind of food out here.
Well worth the drive, too.
FIERI: Or how about
well worth the flight?
The planes flying overhead
making all the noise
were these gentlemen
from the Thunderbirds
out of Las Vegas.
MAN: We were flying overhead and
smelled some pretty great food,
so I decided,
"Hey, we got to land
and come here
and check it out."
Not a bad move.
How many performances
do you do a year?
We'll do 60 shows a year.
This year we're performing
at about 34 different locations.
We get to represent so many men
and women that are deployed.
What a job.
FIERI: As for me, I'm gonna
hang out a little longer.
Not a bad gig.
Crispy pork belly
in the window.
I don't even know
what to say.
When we come back.
FIERI:
In Parkland, Wisconsin,
you don't need a citation to go
to The Kounty Quarthouse.
Just a big appetite.
MAN:
Food is absolutely amazing.
Everything here is scratch-made
and it's wonderful.
FIERI: And it's bringing in
all kinds of folks.
We have a lot of seniors,
we have a lot of foodies.
Country folk, city folk,
all kinds of people.
Even the Air Force Thunderbirds
dropped in
for a taste
of Beth Cherny's kitchen.
You come to a funky little joint
like this
on a country road.
What do you think?
I love it.
It's good. Great.
WOMAN: Beth, I know,
puts her whole heart
into everything
she makes homemade.
Crispy pork belly
in the window.
MAN: Pork belly's kind of like
a mix between bacon and ham.
It's meat candy.
FIERI:
What are we making now?
Okay, we're gonna make
the braising liquid
for our
pork belly sandwich.
Okay.
I start with some water
and some soy sauce.
Add some brown sugar.
Little oil, some minced garlic,
and some black pepper.
I don't like to submerge
the entire fat top,
just so that some of the fat
can braise of the belly itself.
This goes in the oven
uncovered.
Uncovered for?
375.
For how long?
2½ hours.
Dig it. Next up?
We're gonna make the dressing
for our slaw
that goes on top
of the pork belly.
Vegetable oil.
Got it.
Soy sauce.
Red wine vinegar.
And a little black pepper.
We just whisk that up.
Green cabbage.
Plain old green cabbage.
Carrots.
Green onions.
And a little...
Cilantro.
...cilantro.
Okay, now we're gonna assemble
the pork belly sandwich.
All right.
We're gonna take
our pork belly
that's been braised
and cooled down.
And then we're going
to dredge it in rice flour.
What are you doing
with rice flour
out here
on County K Road?
It's crispier and lighter.
All right,
now we're gonna deep-fry it?
Yes.
Great.
We're gonna take
a warm ciabatta roll.
Wasabi mayo and then
our crispy pork belly.
Ridiculous.
And then we're gonna take
a little bit
of our slaw that we made.
We dress it.
Tell me when.
When.
That's good.
And then add the Asian barbecue
on top of that.
Stack it up?
Yep.
[ Whistles ]
How is one
going to enjoy this?
The stance.
You know the hunch?
You made it look more
like some kind of a --
Crawl?
...creep.
[ Laughs ]
I don't even know
what to say.
That was awesome.
That's a great sandwich.
Pork belly --
chewy, unctuous, porky.
The slaw not being made
ahead of time
has got great crunch to it.
You get a little bit
of that heat
coming through
from the wasabi.
It is every bit
an Asian pork belly sandwich
from the word "go."
You rock.
MAN: You got the kind
of crispiness of the meat
and it's also tender.
Then you got the nice crunch
of the slaw.
It's just perfect.
I'm full, satisfied,
and I will be back next week.
FIERI: Well, guys,
I'll tell you something.
It's been a pleasure,
and thank you very much,
and it's great to have you
on "Triple D."
Thank you.
Now, eat it up,
'cause you guys got to go.
You're double parked.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI:
Coming up in Jackson, Wyoming...
Oh, I love it.
...the bomb bison...
Holy Bombay bowl.
...parked right next
to the killer curry.
You're rocking this, girl.
I'm here at Jackson, Wyoming,
or Jackson Hole,
as a lot of people call it.
So, I'm in the downtown area
to check out a restaurant
that's serving exactly
what you'd expect.
That's right -- 100% organic
from the meats to the veggies.
This is Lotus Cafe.
Veggie burger with quinoa.
The food tastes like what
it's supposed to taste like.
I think Amy's done
a really unique thing here.
FIERI: That would be chef
Amy Young, who zeroed in
on what she loves when
she opened this joint in '07.
I worked in a lot of restaurants
in these small mountain towns
so I could be a ski bum,
but I also had this passion
for natural foods.
Bombay with bison.
It's part of the Jackson Hole
experience.
A good balance between super
healthy and a little naughty.
FIERI: The Bombay bowl.
You can add tofu,
you can add tempeh.
Tempe, Arizona?
[ Rimshot ]
Be here all week.
Try the tempeh.
Today we're making it
with bison.
How do we start off?
Are we making the...
The sauce that goes
on top of the Bombay bowl.
So, lemon juice,
fresh minced ginger.
Lots of it.
Sea salt, black pepper,
red chili flake,
cumin, cinnamon.
This all gets whipped up.
Whip it good.
Mm-hmm.
Vegan mayo.
It's made
with safflower oil.
It's whipped
until super creamy.
And here's our spice mixture
that we made.
Mix it up real good.
So, we're doing bison
for the Bombay bowl.
Black pepper,
cayenne, cumin.
Granulated garlic.
Chili powder,
and sea salt.
Ooh.
I like the magic.
Next up?
Onions, garlic.
So, the bison goes down.
The bison spice mixture.
Exactly.
And the 'zackly.
And hit it with
a little more safflower.
Okay,
so the bison's working.
Now we get the basmati.
Our sautéed vegetables,
baby spinach, carrots.
Got it.
Fresh mango.
Mango tango.
Roasted coconut.
Bison.
Holy Bombay bowl.
The tikka sauce.
It's very rich,
awesome textures.
It's got tons of flavor.
Not bland, not boring.
The veggies are outrageous.
The mango, nice little
fresh bite to it.
The thing that
I'm actually most wowed about
is that vegetarian
mayo concoction.
It adds such a nice
velvety texture.
Oh, I love it.
Killer.
Getting buffalo instead of beef
is very Wyoming-esque.
WOMAN: There's a stereotype
about healthy restaurants.
It's gonna taste gross
and be all weeds and stuff.
FIERI:
Well, we're gonna test that
on the dudes
working across the street.
This is Amy.
She's the owner.
Bombay bowl with bison
and bison tacos.
Pass it around.
I love my veggies.
MAN:
Oh, that's delicious.
Oh, it's good.
FIERI:
Out of bounds, man.
[ Laughter ]
MAN:
Everything is fabulous.
You really get to taste
the full flavor of the food.
Thai noodles.
I'm having the Thai bowl.
It's full of vegetables,
noodles, and spicy curry.
When we make curry here,
we don't mess around.
A lot of Thai curry,
you see it really thick.
We make it as a broth.
So, here's some lemongrass.
We make a lemongrass tea.
FIERI: How long
do we let this steep?
20 minutes.
Okay.
Now fresh basil.
Gonna push this
down in there
'cause we got to make room
for cilantro.
Serranos.
Garlic.
Got it.
Lemon juice.
And then the galangal.
This stuff takes flavor
to a whole nother level.
Sea salt,
evaporated cane juice.
Evaporated cane juice?
It's very fancy.
Gluten-free tamari.
Little coconut milk here.
And then
the lemongrass tea.
Drop the hammer.
Do it. Do it.
Gonna strain it
through here.
Exactly.
The rest
of our lemongrass tea
and the rest
of our coconut milk.
We got water boiling.
Rice noodles.
Now we're going to add
our broccoli, red bell pepper,
zucchini, thin-sliced,
grass-fed local beef.
So, when this starts boiling,
add the red onion.
The meat cooks up
really quick.
It's super thin sliced.
Garnishes.
Put a little mung bean.
Oh, I love mung bean.
Carrots.
Cilantro.
That's a lot of cilantro.
But, you know,
it's really good for you.
Scallion.
Oh, you got the touch.
Okay.
Oh, yeah.
It's an orchestra.
It's all these flavors
and all these textures
together in one bowl.
Tender noodles,
great broth.
You could soak
anything in it.
You're rocking this, girl.
Keow!
It's my very favorite dish.
It's really tasty stuff.
Always just a pleasure
coming in here.
I don't know
what you're doing
next time
you're in Jackson Hole
besides snowmobiling or hiking
with seaweed snacks,
but when you have a chance,
make sure you make time.
Come down to Lotus Cafe.
Girl's off the hook!
FIERI:
Up next in Lancaster, Oregon...
It's crazy.
...a place known
for going all out...
I'm gonna take the rest
of the month to enjoy this.
...in taking their menu
to the max.
Look at that hummingbird bite
I took out of it.
So, I'm here on the 99E highway
about 17 miles
from Eugene, Oregon,
97 miles from Portland in this
little farming community.
Now, this is an unincorporated
town called Lancaster,
and the lady that owns the town,
well, her son happens to own
the only restaurant in town.
Now, you think
that's interesting,
wait till you see the menu.
This is Junkyard
Extreme Burger & Brats.
KIM: I've got a Wisconsin
and a Chicago.
I'm a big eater and I like big
hamburgers and big hot dogs,
and this is definitely it.
You can expect to get messy.
We never suffer from lack
of food when we come here.
FIERI: And that's how owners
Craig and Kim Zumwalt like it --
big and bold.
After working
in Nashville's music biz,
Craig headed back home
and opened this place in '06.
FIERI: How many people
live here in Lancaster?
CRAIG:
Probably about 30.
Wow.
Is this a trailer?
It's a race trailer.
And then you built the shed
on next to it?
Yes.
Awesome.
And they're definitely
trying to kick it into gear
when it comes to their
high-octane signature burger.
I've got a big block.
The burger is bigger
than my head.
That huge.
This is just explosion
of taste, literally.
I mean, 'cause there's just
so many ingredients in it.
We're gonna make
a big block.
FIERI: Big block, okay.
Let's do it.
We have our bread
made for us. Then --
Koosh!
We need to put some butter
on that.
Bring a little parmesan,
put it right across there.
Bring out
some burger here.
Looks like about a half-pounder
right there to me.
Yeah, that works.
We'll get two of those.
It's a one-pound burger?
Yeah. One-pound burger.
Now we're gonna just throw this
on here like this.
We're just gonna take this
and concave it a little bit.
Grab a little onion.
Gonna throw on
a little bit of bacon.
Going right in the middle.
Yep.
Gonna smash her down.
Get it caramelized
real good.
Now we're gonna cut a hole
in the middle of the bun.
We're gonna add an egg.
Now we're gonna add a little
cheddar cheese sauce.
About like that.
Put a little cheddar on the top.
Is this the family plan?
Yes.
All right. Now we're gonna build
a cheese skirt.
We're gonna start out
with a little parmesan.
Cheddar, onion,
mozzo, bacon.
Does it come
with a heart paddle?
[ Laughs ] Right?
Stack on a little bacon.
We're gonna stick this dome
on top there.
So, our cheese is just
about ready to roll here.
Just so everybody's
up to speed,
close to a cup of cheese has
been assembled in this abuse --
I mean this dish.
Well, it looks like
everything's ready.
Now we're gonna take this,
slam that right over on that.
And we're gonna take this guy,
put it right there.
Add a little lettuce.
We got this.
Mayonnaise.
Tomato.
Don't overdo it.
No, I won't.
Mo' meat.
More mayo.
Pickle.
There we go.
Little more lettuce.
Little sprig of onion.
Big block.
There it is.
You have a scale?
Right here.
3.4 pounds.
Probably all lettuce
and tomato.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Grunts ]
That's ridiculous.
Look at that hummingbird bite
I took out of it.
So...
Well, I'm gonna take the rest
of the month to enjoy this.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm.
Here's the thing, buddy.
I've seen some big blocks
in the design
and disaster category.
You've pretty much taken
first place on that.
I got that going for me.
Which is nice.
Yeah.
Way to go.
KIM: Big block.
The best part about it
is the meat,
it just melts in your mouth.
You have to laugh when this
thing shows up at your table.
It's like, "How are you gonna
finish it all?"
FIERI: Well, you could always
take it to go,
because this place also
has one funky drive-through.
This is a total
farm community,
so they drive up
in everything --
horses, combines, tractors,
you name it.
Bo and Luke Duke
come by often?
Okay, I've got a party in your
mouth and a fried cheese pizza.
Today I'm having
the fried cheese pizza.
The best part is the cheese,
and that's what the crust is.
And what are
we gonna make?
We're gonna make
crustless pizza.
It's a fried cheese pizza.
The temple of health.
You guys should have a gym
right next to this place.
All right, let's hit it.
Take our pineapple right
over here to the grill.
Boom.
Take our parmesan like so.
Cheddar.
Onion.
Little Gorgonzola.
All the members
of the cheese family
are showing up for this.
Pepperoni.
Throw a little mozzarella
on there.
More cheese?
More cheese.
Now we're gonna run
that homemade pizza sauce
right across here.
Little olive.
Now we're gonna throw
on our grilled pineapple,
then our in-house pesto.
Take our dome.
Voilà.
Cooks for maybe
2½, 3 minutes.
[ Whistles ]
So, we're gonna top it
with some sliced tomatoes.
We're gonna cut it.
Wow, that holds up
a lot better
than I thought
it was going to.
Mm-hmm.
This right here is just
a gigantic thing
of that crunchy fried cheese
that you love
on the outside of a quesadilla.
The fact that you put
toppings on it, it's crazy.
Look at that.
Fried cheese.
Can't beat it.
Okay, here, Carrie.
Here's your fried cheese pizza.
It's extremely addicting.
You have to share it.
Everybody wants to try it.
I've never seen a fried cheese
pizza anywhere else.
Junkyard is unique foods
that you just can't find
anywhere else.
This is a hidden gem.
I'm telling you, dude,
we've seen some crazy stuff
on "Triple D."
This is up there.
Crazy Craig
in the car carrier.
Loving it.
Very nice, brother.
So, that's it for this road
trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You do a lot of making
for such a little thing.
You got to do
what you got to do
with what you got
to do with.
...What you got to do.
That is true.
[ Laughter ]