Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Holy moly!
...this '68's revved up...
Hit it.
Don't babysit it.
...for a tour of
cross-country classics...
I was cruising down
Boring Avenue,
hooked a right,
right onto Delicious Boulevard.
...in Carmel, California.
That's crazy.
An extreme,
comfort-food fill-up...
That's pretty
out-of-bounds.
...with my brother
from another mother...
What are you laughing at?
FIERI:
In Superior, Wisconsin...
[ Imitates rimshot ] And he'll
be here all week, folks.
...a meaty pizzeria...
How much meat is
going on this?
...that's totally
piling up their pies.
It's a meat-lover's!
You got to have a lot of meat!
And in Somerville,
Massachusetts...
[ Laughs ]
...the funky
neighborhood lounge...
"You're gonna have
the chicken and waffles!"
...giving New Englanders
some true Southern comfort.
I'm moving in.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm just like you.
I like to go on road trips
with my buddies,
check out funky joints,
eat great food.
So here I am in Carmel,
California,
to check out a joint
where I hear they're
scratch-making everything,
and the biscuits are the bomb.
This is From Scratch.
Okay, Robert,
no more driving.
Time to come in and eat.
Let's go.
Aw, Dad! I thought you said
I could drive!
Cinnamon French toast
in the window.
California dip
on our homemade roll.
Homey, delicious meals.
They put a little love in it.
FIERI: And that love
comes from the family tree,
because when Steven Grebing
and his wife, Carolyn,
bought the joint in '95,
he most certainly
tapped into his roots.
Where did you learn to cook?
My mother and my grandmother.
Okay, so it's old-school, then.
Old-school.
Yeah, old-school in hyperdrive.
Extreme double sausage,
biscuits, and gravy.
You have a little sausage,
gravy,
but then you have a sausage
patty under the sausage gravy.
And then
cheese biscuits under that.
FIERI: Good thing I got
my health-nut compadre
Chef Robert Irvine
along for the ride.
I have already been
in the gym two hours,
and I've eaten breakfast
at 8:00.
I want you to count
just how many times
we will talk about the gym,
how many times
we'll see flexing.
Don't hate this.
It's hard work.
[ British accent ]
It's a machine.
I put a lot of time
in it.
Have you had
a biscuit and gravy?
I have many times.
So, tell me about
the biscuits, then.
So, we're gonna start
with the flour.
We put in powdered milk.
Then we're gonna add some sugar
and baking soda,
Salt.
[ Normal voice ] Okay.
Cream of tartar.
Now we add the cream cheese.
This is awesome.
Now,
is it cold cream cheese,
like we're doing
cold butter?
Yeah.
Little bit of butter.
Okay. Okay.
Incorporate that in.
Then we're gonna make up
our wet mix.
Okay.
And to that,
we add buttermilk.
A little bit more melted butter,
baking soda.
Okay, now we mix it up?
Yep.
And then we're gonna add
the cheddar cheese.
And we'll roll it
to about 3/4" thick.
So then we'll cut them.
In the oven, 350,
how long?
For about 35,
40 minutes.
Now we're gonna make
our sausage.
We start with
fresh ground pork.
Just pork? Nothing else?
Just pork. Yeah.
So, to that,
we're gonna add
thyme, marjoram,
sage, ginger.
That's different.
Granulated garlic,
granulated onion,
salt, maple sugar,
sambal chili paste.
And mix it, mix it,
mix it.
Okay, are we gonna give this
a chance to kind of marry,
kind of bring
some flavor together?
We're gonna let this go
for overnight.
Excellent.
Now we're gonna cook
our house-made sausage.
I'm so hungry.
This better be good.
[ British accent ]
All Robert had this morning
was two sips of air
and a brief whiff of coffee.
And it was a whiff.
It's got a great smell.
Now we're gonna start
the gravy,
and we'll add yellow onions,
salt, white pepper.
[ Normal voice ] Some A.P.?
We're gonna build some roux?
Yep.
Are we going full,
heavy cream, half-and-half?
We're going
half-and-half.
And we'll let this simmer,
just tighten up for how long?
About 15, 20 minutes.
Bring out the biscuits,
put it together.
Yes.
Nice biscuit.
There you go.
Give it a nice,
little toast.
We're gonna make two patties
and cook this on the flattop.
We toasted the biscuit up.
Sausage here.
Now we put our sausage
and gravy on there.
Fresh green parsley.
You want to try some?
Here you go.
[ Utensil clinks ]
Oh, what happened
to yours, Robert?
It's like a fight
to get in there.
The cheddar in the biscuit
is bananas.
Then on top of it,
the sausage patty.
But you know what?
It's that sambal
in that sausage patty
that just gives it
a little bit of that extra heat.
Yep.
The gravy's creamy.
And it's
not dry and gritty.
It's thick and pretty.
You have license
to use "extreme," man.
That's pretty out-of-bounds.
Thank you.
Oh, I got to tell you --
it's amazing.
I don't eat fat,
and this is really good.
I mean, it's really good.
Thank you.
Nice job. Excellent job.
Thank you, thank you.
Extreme biscuits and gravy up.
They're fantastic.
These biscuits and gravy
are crazy-good.
I've been to
800 locations.
How many joints you guys been to
on "Triple D"?
262.
That's not a gut
that says "262."
And this is 263 today?
Today. Absolutely.
The menu is so good.
Definitely lots of
comfort food.
I'm gonna go take a small nap,
but before I go,
is there anything else
you have up your sleeve?
You got to try --
Don't tell us.
You guys want more?
You want to see
more of Robert Irvine,
From Scratch in Carmel?
See you in a little bit.
Welcome back.
Guy Fieri and my brother from
another mother, Robert Irvine,
hanging out
at this funky place,
called From Scratch
in Carmel, California.
We needed
that entire commercial break
just to come out of
the food [exhales sharply] coma.
Speak for yourself.
I was doing push-ups
and star jumps.
Yeah,
push-ups in his sleep
'cause he was asleep on the back
booth over by where I was.
[ Laughing ]
All right, Chef,
what are we making?
We're gonna make From Scratch
brisket chili.
The meat is tender
and the right blend of spicy.
WOMAN:
If I could make chili, I wish
I could make it like this.
It's amazing.
We start
with a full brisket.
Doctor. Doctor.
And we're gonna cube it
and go with the one-inch cube.
Dig it.
From Scratch house seasoning
that we make.
When we cook,
we layer flavors, right?
This is important --
to season every step of the way.
All right, let's go.
We're gonna sear it
on the flattop.
Okay.
Okay, so, now you got it
browned all the way around.
Now we'll hit it
with a little onion.
Caramelize those a bit.
Yep.
Now where are we at?
Well, we're gonna build
our chili.
Hit it.
We'll start off with our
fresh-made chicken stock.
We got the beef stock.
Chili powder
that we blended.
That you made yourself.
Chicken base, beef base,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion.
Fresh, toasted cumin.
Cocoa powder.
You got to have a little
chocolate in the bottom of
that. I'll give it to you.
Chopped garlic.
Seared-off brisket
with the onions.
Crushed tomatoes.
Tomato paste.
A little raisin paste.
Okay.
And then
we'll add one beer.
We'll let that cook down
a little bit.
How long?
For an hour.
Plate up our chili.
Okay.
I'm gonna use
red kidney beans.
From dry. I love that.
Incredible.
It's rich. It's flavorful.
The meat's tender,
but you find the meat.
Right, and that's
why you cube it large.
You taste the little sweetness
of the raisin in there,
just counterbalance
that heat.
I get a couple levels
of sweetness.
That's a phenomenal chili.
Thank you.
Just the right amount
of heat.
We're gonna have to go to
the gym after this, aren't we?
Yep.
Brisket chili.
MAN: I like it because it's got
big chunks of meat in it.
They don't play around.
WOMAN: It's not too hot,
but it's spicy.
It's the best chili I've had.
Chef, had a great time.
Thank you, Guy.
And he's gonna send me some of
the biscuits and gravy.
Peace.
FIERI: Coming up...
What is this?!
...in Superior, Wisconsin...
It's a pizza-cutter.
That's illegal
in 49 states!
...a pizzeria slinging
smoked meat...
This is nuts.
...right next to
some serious sandwiches.
I'll take some of that.
So, it's July here in
beautiful Superior, Wisconsin,
right over the bridge
from Duluth, Minnesota.
You know, with the weather
the way it is around here,
I'm told, "Spend as much time
indoors as you can."
So I'm here to check out a joint
everybody loves.
This is Shorty's Pizza
and Smoked Meats.
Large Santa Fe.
Wow. It's delicious.
It's not just pizzas.
They have sandwiches and burgers
and appetizers.
Pepper burger's up.
This is the only restaurant
that I know in Superior
that has the smoked meats.
WOMAN: Hot turkey sandwich
with coleslaw.
This is a very good place to
come in the cold weather.
WOMAN: You're right up
on Lake Superior,
as far north as you can get
before Canada.
FIERI: Which is where the menu
inspiration came from
when Brian Noel
opened the joint up in 2013.
Coming from Ottawa, Canada,
a smoked meat is
kind of like the American
version of a hamburger.
And so I thought
I'd bring it up here.
And hand off the technique
to restaurant vet and Chef
David Andert.
More smoked meat, Scottie.
The smoked meat is just so good.
WOMAN: Here's the meat-lover's
pizza for you guys.
There are pizzas,
and then there are pizzas.
And this meat-lover's pizza
we have in front of us
is fantastic.
FIERI: So,
what are we gonna make, man?
Putting together the dry rub
for our smoked meat
for the meat-lover's pizza.
[ Canadian accent ]
The smoked meat.
The Canadian-style
smoked meat.
[ Normal voice ] Oh, yeah.
Cinnamon, curing salt,
garlic powder,
allspice.
Holy moly!
[ Whistles ]
Pickling salt, sugar,
and pickling seasoning.
Okay.
Mix it up really good.
Now we're gonna score
the fat cap of the brisket.
Okay.
Set that in there
like that.
And then we're gonna put all
the dry rub over the top of it.
No water or anything?
Nothing else is going in that?
Nothing.
Sits like this for five days.
Then what happens?
I put it in the Alto-Shaam.
I slow-bake it for six hours.
Six hours, low and slow.
Okay.
Wow!
I scrape all the dry rub
off it,
being careful not to take
the fat off...
Got it.
...'cause that's
where all your flavor is.
This is nuts.
Wrap it air-tight again.
I leave it sit for, at least,
two more days in the cooler.
Everybody thought the world
was made in seven days.
It was brisket.
[ Imitates rimshot ] And he'll
be here all week, folks.
Try the pizza.
We start with the sauce.
Nice and chunky.
Pepperoni on first.
Now we put the sausage on.
Raw?
Raw.
A little bit of bacon.
How much meat
is going on this?!
It's a meat-lover's!
You got to have a lot of meat!
[ Imitates whooshing ]
What is this?!
It's a pizza cutter.
That's illegal
in 49 states!
Now,
ladies and gentlemen...
The smoked meat.
And we put right about
a pound of cheese on here.
Here we go.
What temperature is the oven?
550 degrees.
Give that about eight minutes.
Eight minutes,
and we'll be ready to go?
Yes, sir.
Look at this thing.
[ Metal clangs ]
It's crispy. It's chewy.
Sausage adds tons of flavor.
You get the herbs
from the smoked meat.
Great job, Chef.
Thank you. Thank you.
This guy's crazy.
Pizza up!
I'm from Wisconsin. I like
cheese. That's a lot of cheese.
The smoked meat with
the bacon and the sausage,
it is just to die for.
FIERI:
All right, I get the food,
but I'm just
not getting the name.
No one has been
able to answer,
"Where did 'Shorty's'
come from?"
You're far from short.
The building is enormous.
We just wanted to have a fun,
simple, easy name to remember.
Just Shorty's.
Correct.
WOMAN:
It's a very unique place.
It's a blend of old and new,
just the best food in town.
Drop me
another hunter's chicken.
The hunter's
chicken sandwich --
unbelievably good,
really, really moist chicken.
It's worth every bite.
I picked this item
because my son's name
is Hunter.
Yeah. I figured that.
All right, so, let's get
into the hunter's chicken.
Okay.
Red wine.
So we're making
a red-wine reduction?
Demiglace.
Okay.
Gonna let that reduce down
to about 1/4 of
what we started with.
And then we're gonna get
the bacon grease
so it melts down,
gets hot.
Mix the butter, the garlic,
the shallots,
bacon,
and a few mushrooms.
We're gonna let that
reduce down.
Now I'm gonna go and add
the red-wine,
demiglace reduction.
What we're gonna do now is
season the chicken breast.
What is that
we just put on there?
This is a garlic-herb blend.
Okay.
Little bit of butter.
Put it on the flat-top.
Put a press on it
so we get a nice,
crisp skin on the outside.
Except there's no skin
on it.
There's no skin.
[ Laughs ]
Pull this off.
You slice it
on the bias here.
Back on the grill.
You take provolone cheese,
put it over the top.
Put a cap
over the top of that.
Give it a little shot of water
and melt that cheese down.
There you go.
I like your method.
And put it on our grilled
cranberry, wild-rice bread.
Take our sauce...
...and serve it.
If any one component of
this sandwich wasn't there,
this would be
a pretty basic sandwich.
Yet, you took it to
a variety of different levels --
one,
with the hunter sauce.
Putting the crisp on
the chicken, that's a necessity.
Cut it on the bias
and you make it very delicate
to eat.
It's a great flavor. I was
cruising down Boring Avenue,
hooked a right,
right onto Delicious Boulevard.
You navigated this into
a really dynamite sandwich.
Thank you.
Hunter chicken
in the window.
The chicken, the cheese,
the mushrooms --
it just melts in your mouth.
I'll tell you something, man --
it's a great place.
Great pizza, scratch-made food,
good times, man.
Thank you.
Good times.
Shorty's Pizza
and Smoked Meat.
FIERI: Up next,
it's Somerville, Massachusetts.
[ Chuckles ]
Good, old-fashioned
home cooking...
These are for me.
...fired up --
where else on "Triple D"?
You're right.
In the back of a bar.
That's good fried chicken,
like your mom would make.
I'm here in Cambridge,
Massachusetts,
right outside of Boston,
to check out a joint
where they're --
well, actually I'm in
Somerville, Massachusetts --
to check out --
Well, regardless,
if I'm in Cambridge,
Massachusetts or Somerville,
I'm right on the line.
But I'm here to check out
a joint
that's scratch-making
upscale bar food.
This is Trina's Starlite Lounge.
Spaghetti and meatballs.
It's a bar,
but it's not bar food.
MAN: I would describe
the food here as comfort food.
It warms the soul
after a hard day's work.
It kind of looks like
a hole in the wall.
It used to be an old rock venue,
and these guys brought it back
to life as a great restaurant.
FIERI: Part of that CPR team is
Executive Chef Suzi Maitland.
She's been serving up
her Southern spin
ever since the place opened
in '09, right on the city line.
Do they understand
Southern food here?
They do. There's
a really big market for it.
MAN: I'm from the South
originally, so it's really hard
moving up North and not,
you know, getting that
hometown flavor.
But here, they really get it.
Chicken and waffles up.
The chicken waffles here
is the best I've ever had.
And you wouldn't expect that
from New England.
What are we making?
So, we'll be making
our fried chicken
and buttermilk waffles.
It's our biggest seller.
Whose recipe?
My recipe.
You're using breasts
and thighs and legs.
Mm-hmm.
We're gonna
do buttermilk first.
Paprika.
Little bit of garlic.
Dried marjoram.
Marjoram, really?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Nice floral.
How long's this
gonna marinate?
Overnight.
We're gonna go ahead
and make the chicken dredge.
Let's get after this.
Flour, paprika,
dried marjoram,
dried thyme,
tarragon, mustard.
Loading it up.
Cayenne, baking powder,
and salt.
So it's salty. It's hot.
We're gonna dredge it
and let it set.
And then we're gonna throw it
right in the fryer.
350.
Cook it off till it browns.
What temp in the oven?
350, as well.
Now we'll be making
the waffle.
[ Both laugh ]
Buttermilk.
Eggs, honey,
salt, little bit of
baking powder,
and then sugar,
and our fried-chicken dredge.
I'm just gonna
mix that up.
So more
of a savory waffle.
Exactly.
And then we're gonna add
melted butter.
And are we gonna
spray this or...
We are, indeed.
[ Chuckles ]
How long
does that take?
About two minutes.
It is ready.
[ Whistles ]
And then
our fried chicken.
When I drove up here,
some person yelled to me
from the neighborhood and said,
"You're gonna have
the chicken and waffles!"
[ Chuckling ] Really?
That's awesome!
And then we're gonna do
a little bit of salt,
a little bit of a chive,
and then hot-pepper syrup.
That's good fried chicken,
like your mom would make.
Mmm.
Chicken's moist as can be,
nice, little crunch.
That savory component really
elevates the experience.
I got to say,
"You got it going on, girl."
MAITLAND:
Fried chicken and waffles.
The waffle's nice and fluffy.
Perfectly fried chicken
every time.
How late do
they serve the food?
Midnight.
[ Scoffs ]
I'm moving in.
FIERI:
And with those kind of hours,
they got plenty of time
for a scratch-made take
on one of my favorite snacks.
Tater tots up.
Tots are perfect.
They're perfect.
Come on!
You can tell
they're not store-bought.
They are very obviously
made in-house.
Next, we'll be making
our handmade tater tots.
Russets?
Yep. Idaho.
So, we're just gonna shred them
in the Robot Coupe.
Now we're just gonna put it
into water to rinse it off.
Squeeze all that water out.
Keep it from browning.
That's it?
That's it.
So, then we're gonna take
corn starch,
and we're really gonna coat
the potatoes.
And then we're just gonna
sprinkle potatoes
on a sheet pan.
And then we're just gonna put
this in the oven
for about 20 minutes.
What temp? Got it.
400.
Basically,
it steams them.
There's texture.
They're not soggified.
Let's see the rest of it,
girl.
We're gonna put on
some Spanish onions,
salt, garlic powder,
chives.
Just mix it all together
with our hands.
And then ball it.
Okay, now, take them
to the fryer? 350?
350.
Bring me the tots.
[ Chuckles ]
So, we're just
gonna salt them
and then plate them with our
rosemary-garlic aioli
and a little parmesan,
chives.
Done.
[ Sniffs ]
I got good news,
and I got bad news.
What do you want first?
Bad news.
Bad news --
these are for me.
The good news is
they're really good.
Really? Awesome.
The garlic powder
inside of them, I think, is key.
The components
that you've done,
drying them out
in the oven,
not overcooking them.
In the world of tots
that I come from,
that's a good tot.
Thank you.
WOMAN: Tater tots.
They almost taste like mashed
potatoes that are deep-fried.
Nice and soft on the inside,
crispy on the outside.
It's the perfect bite.
I know I can come down here
and I'm gonna know somebody
and I know I'm gonna get
great food and great service
and a great drink.
Here's the deal --
watching you cook,
you enjoy it.
And you get
tremendous pleasure
from making food,
following your disciplines.
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip.
But don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
♪ "Triple D"
came to my city ♪
♪ Got me working here
every night and day ♪
♪ Got to get ready for
Mr. Guy Fieri ♪
♪ Got to show him
how I do it my way ♪
[ Laughter ]