Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Holy moly!
...we're rocking the retro...
Why this works,
I do not know.
...at some off-the-hook,
old-school joints.
This is Crazytown --
next to Flavortown.
In Delta, Wisconsin...
Houston,
we have a problem.
...a righteous,
real-deal diner...
Probably in the top three
best pancakes I've ever had
on "Triple D."
...smack-dab
in the middle of nowhere.
I'm freaked out!
In Duluth, Minnesota...
Whoa.
...a legit
Italian family market...
Dude, you can work
some dough.
...that's not skimping
on the staples.
Noodle, noodle,
noodle, noodle, noodle,
cheese, cheese, cheese,
meat, meat, meat,
meat, meat, meat.
And in Eugene, Oregon...
Here you go, "Triple D."
...a throwback café...
Let me see the magic.
...serving up a killer
comfort curve ball.
You could have named it
"Funkalicious."
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
I have had so many buddies
tell me,
"Guido, I have got the perfect
'Triple D' join for you.
I mean, I used to go there
when I was in high school."
"My cousin owns it."
"It's got the best burger."
I mean, the list goes on and on,
but to be honest with you,
maybe 1 in 1,000 of those stick.
Now, I'm here
in Delta, Wisconsin.
Don't trust your GPS
when you come to this place
because I even got lost.
It is in the middle of nowhere.
But don't worry.
This comes
with a great recommendation
from a very reliable source,
and that's me,
'cause I was here a year ago,
and I knew I'd bring
"Triple D" back.
This is Delta Diner.
BUCHER: Order up.
I love it here.
It's our food church.
They built it,
and people are coming.
There is nothing for miles,
and then all of a sudden --
boom!
It's kind of like a mirage
in a way,
a red, white, and blue beacon
here in the middle
of the Chequamegon Forest.
The first thing that came
to mind is, "Why here?"
FIERI: A question only
founder Todd Bucher can answer.
[ Laughter ]
We moved up here. Not really
sure what we were gonna do.
We understood
the passion of diners,
and we got this inkling
to put a diner here.
He discovered this piece
of the past back east in '03,
then had it restored and shipped
out here to the Northwoods.
Here's the pig and pepper
omelet.
The menu is eclectic,
whatever that means.
We've got a red-eye gravy up.
It's a rich, dark gravy
that they serve
on buttermilk biscuits.
You taste a little
of the coffee, the meat,
a little bit of spice.
I dream of it, really.
It's heavenly, you know?
I am a red-eye gravy
aficionado.
I was in
the red-eye gravy navy.
This is red-eye gravy
on biscuits with prime rib?
Yep.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's gravy, baby.
All right, let's hit it, man.
We're gonna do
prime rib first.
It's got a great little rub
that goes on it.
Olive oil.
Lebanese Breeze --
pure whipped garlic.
Oh-ho!
Got black pepper.
Some nice rosemary.
And we're just gonna
whip this together.
Okay.
Just gonna kosher salt,
rub it in a little bit.
This -- can't put
too much of this on there.
Now we're gonna tie it?
Ah, give me four.
Doctor.
[ Laughs ]
So, you're doing that
so you keep
the tail of that rib eye
from drying out.
Absolutely.
You culinary gangster.
Roast it in the oven.
Low and slow -- 225.
Going medium-rare.
Yep.
Gonna let it rest.
Chop it into chunks.
That's the beginning
of the red-eye gravy.
Yep.
Bacon first.
We want this to brown up
a little bit.
Okay.
And then, of course, pork.
That is full-blown
swine-and-dine.
Look at that.
Prime in.
Garlic.
Give that
about 30 seconds.
Cayenne and black pepper.
Very nice.
Now we are doing --
Oh, oh, oh.
We're not gonna make coffee
and then add it to it?
No. No.
We're putting
these really nice
Turkish ground
espresso bean in here.
That's what gives it the really
dramatic coffee flavor.
Houston,
we have a problem.
Honey.
We've got
some condensed milk.
I'm freaked out.
And we got some cream.
Chicken broth.
Pork broth.
This is crazy.
I'm actually scared.
Let her simmer.
Gonna turn into this just rich,
wonderful, dark gravy.
In the meantime,
we make the biscuits?
Yes.
So, we got all-purpose flour,
cake flour, salt.
Baking powder.
Baking soda.
And we're just gonna
mix that up.
Cubed, chilled butter.
Got it.
Chilled butter.
Buttermilk.
The key to this
is just fold it in.
We don't want
to work this too much.
Plop her in the middle.
That's barely
holding together.
We're just gonna form it
into a round.
That's it?
That's it.
You cut it
before you put it on?
Mm-hmm.
That's how
she's gonna bake?
Just like that.
350, about 13 minutes.
Last but not least?
We're gonna add
some of the hot gravy to a roux.
It's almost solid.
You throw the warm stuff on it.
Mix her up.
Get the whisk to it.
Turns to a nice slurry.
All right, back in.
[ Whistles ]
So, now this is just gonna
thicken up a little bit.
This is one of the funkiest
red-eye gravies
we have ever seen
in the history of "Triple D."
Here's our biscuits.
I think to do this
the right way,
I'm gonna try to load it up
with all of the bacon,
the sausage,
and the prime rib.
Mmm!
Juicy meat, great texture,
little bit of salt,
little bit of sweetness,
really nice biscuit.
Super coffee flavor.
Coffee leads here.
This is Crazytown --
next to Flavortown.
Mm.
The more you eat it,
the more it grows on you.
Yeah.
Mm!
The beef in it
is just to die for.
I don't even like coffee, but I
really love the espresso in it.
And the biscuits are light
and fluffy and fantastic.
This is the kind of place
that you root for.
This is the experience
you have to have.
If you think this is unique
and interesting and adventurous,
wait till you try the...
Jalapeño hot cakes.
You're gonna love them.
FIERI:
That's when we come back.
Welcome back,
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
in Delta, Wisconsin,
and let me introduce you
to the wild, wild west family
of the Liautauds.
That would be my buddy,
Jimmy John Liautaud.
That's right -- the dude
from Jimmy John's Sandwiches.
So, we're hanging out here
at the Delta Diner,
a place that I discovered
with this crazy family
a year ago, and now "Triple D"
is finally here.
This is Big Jim.
Now, did you find it,
or did Jimmy find it?
I think I found it.
You think you found it?
Okay.
We had some fantastic
red-eye gravy made
with more coffee grounds
than should ever be put
into any dish.
It was outstanding,
and it just gets
crazy from here.
Pancakes with jalapeños.
It sounds crazy,
but they're awesome.
FIERI:
Yep, you heard it right --
jalapeño hot cakes.
Outrageous.
So, let's get it going.
We'll start out
with the dry.
All-purpose flour.
Sugar.
Baking powder.
A little bit of cinnamon
and salt.
All right,
just mix this together.
Set it aside.
Eggs.
That's a lot of egg,
baby.
Mix those up.
Jimmy, can you pour the vanilla?
Are you helping now?
I'm helping.
All right!
This is really nice.
Milk.
Want me to stir this
for you?
Yeah.
Come on, Jimmy.
You know how to cook.
All right.
There we go.
Just keep her going.
Jimmy and his family
have this great little cabin
that we go to ever year.
And we were hanging out
one day,
and Jimmy says, "I'm gonna
take you to this great diner."
Then I have
this Norwegian pancake,
so I knew that we would be
coming back here.
Melted butter.
A lot of butter,
and this makes what I would call
a not very thick batter.
No.
It's gonna be thin.
It goes in a container,
goes in the fridge.
We've had a chance
for the pancake batter to rest.
Onto the griddle?
This is it.
Let's see it.
All right.
Now you're gonna throw on
chopped pickled jalapeño.
Yep.
This does not look like
it should work at all.
Now you smell
the jalapeños
starting to caramelize
a little bit on the grill.
We're gonna sprinkle
the powdered sugar on it.
All right, so, everybody,
here's what you do.
Grab that lemon.
Squeeze it around
on top of that.
Why this works,
I do not know.
[ Laughs ]
I don't say it very often,
but this is probably
in the top three
best pancakes I've ever had
on "Triple D,"
if not the best.
It's tender. It's light.
It's thin.
Kind of think about it
like a crepe gone wild.
And it is sweet.
That's a sweet batter.
It's nice and eggy.
And the lemon and the sugar
just cut the hot perfectly.
It's an amazing
combination.
Leslie Liautaud,
what do you think?
The jalapeño is not hot.
It's savory.
so you get a perfect
savory and sweet mixture.
MAN: I get caught
between texture and flavor.
They're both vying
for all your attention.
YOUNG MAN:
It's really just amazing.
I didn't expect it
to be this great.
It's worth a special journey
to get here.
So, there you are,
in the real-deal diner
in the middle of nowhere.
Adios!
Coming up,
in Duluth, Minnesota...
That is thick and dense.
...a doing-it-all
Italian spot...
All day long.
...serving it up family-style.
So, it's full-on
"Brady Bunch."
FIERI: If you've been watching
"Triple D" for a while,
you know I'm a huge fan
of Italian markets.
I mean,
I don't know what it is.
Maybe it's my heritage.
Maybe it's the fact
that you can go in,
it's part grocery store
and part deli
and you can get a little snack
or a little Italian specialty.
I mean, the list goes on and on.
So, I'm here in
the Spirit Valley neighborhood
right outside of
Duluth, Minnesota,
to check out a joint where
a family is doing that and more.
This is
Gannucci's Italian Market.
Chicken Parm
and a porchetta, table 6.
Everything is homemade here.
Meatball sub
and muffaletta.
Thank you.
It's family-owned.
It's been in the family
for a while.
FIERI:
That would be since 1978,
and the guy running the ship
since 2011
is owner and chef
Billy Kalligher.
So, now, your family works here?
Your kids work here, as well?
Yep, my wife, my son,
my daughters, yep.
How many daughters
do you have?
Six.
What?
Yeah.
And a son?
Three.
Whoa. Whoa.
It just makes you feel like
you're at home.
Got a lasagna for table 4.
This lasagna ranks as one
of the best that I've ever had.
Lots of good layers,
good cheese.
All right, so,
what are we gonna make first?
Make Italian sausage
for lasagna.
Let's get after it, then.
All right.
I have a pork butt.
Cut up in pieces.
And I'm gonna feed it
through the grinder,
grind away.
Now I'm ready
to season it up.
In goes the ground pork.
I add water, salt,
granulated garlic, fennel seed.
Black pepper.
And some ground anise seed.
How long
will you cook this down?
Just until it's brown.
Smells awesome.
What are we up to now?
Pasta.
Beautiful.
The dough's ready
to be rolled out.
Here we go.
A little flour down.
Roll it out.
Dude, you can work
some dough.
Cut it up.
Now we're gonna boil these
for about 30 seconds.
Okay, once they're done,
in some cold water.
Not completely cooked,
though.
Nope.
Okay, now I'm going to assemble
my lasagna.
First our homemade marinara.
Noodles in.
More marinara
on top of that.
Then I'm going to put
my Italian sausage down.
That is great
Italian sausage.
Thank you.
Top it with some cheese
and then build another layer.
More sauce.
Some good Romano on it,
more sausage,
and this will be the last layer.
Three layers?
Three layers.
And we're gonna cook this off
in the oven. What temp?
About 275, 300, just to bring it
up the temp and melt the cheese.
That's gonna be
out in 45 minutes?
Yep.
Wow.
That is thick and dense.
Low-cal.
Low-cal lasagna.
What I like is,
it's simple,
it's completely balanced,
little saltiness
from that Romano cheese.
The kind of lasagna
I wanted as a kid
was noodle, noodle, noodle,
noodle, noodle,
cheese, cheese, cheese,
meat, meat, meat,
meat, meat, meat.
That's what that is.
All right.
But the ground sausage
really is the foundation of it.
I could eat it
all day long.
Good deal.
All day long.
Outstanding.
Delicious.
KALLIGHER:
Your two lasagnas are up, kiddo.
The pasta's very fresh.
It has a perfect texture.
It's not tough.
It's not chewy.
My grandfather used to make
Italian sausage,
and it tastes
very much like his.
Oh, I definitely get cravings
for this.
I mean, this is funky.
Yeah.
You are right in the middle
of a market.
It's a little like stepping back
into like Little Italy
or something like that.
And part of that old-school
feeling is the deli load
of sandwiches
they're making up fresh,
including an Italian take on
a monster New Orleans classic.
KALLIGHER: Okay, we got
the muffaletta ready.
It's delicious.
It has layers
of different types
of Italian cheeses.
WOMAN:
The bread is sweet.
It contrasts with the spiciness
of the meats on there.
I have to have that at least
once a week when I can.
What are making?
The muffaletta.
Tapenade time.
All right.
Got black olives.
The green olives.
Roasted red peppers,
Kalamata.
Capers.
Capers, baby.
And then some olive oil.
Black pepper.
Oregano.
And the best -- garlic.
Mix this up, let it
kind of marry together.
You bet.
Now we put
the muffaletta together.
You betcha.
Okay, we got our homemade
focaccia bread.
Cut.
Now we get the oil.
First I'm gonna start
with the mozzarella.
Now a layer
of Genoa salami.
Next we'll go
to the provolone.
You ever think about putting
some cheese on this?
[ Laughs ]
Little bit of capocollo
on top.
Holy moly!
[ Chuckles ]
And now for the tapenade.
On goes the top.
This is our homemade
dipping sauce.
Got vinegars
and pepper juice,
and that makes it.
If you love
Italian cold cuts,
if you love brininess and salty,
this is your sandwich.
The richness and all these
different components.
And the dipping sauce
is righteous, man.
Yeah, that's good stuff.
This is how you make it.
This is the Gannucci way.
Outstanding.
All right.
WOMAN:
Here's your muffaletta.
Thank you.
WOMAN: The olives on the
muffaletta sandwich are great.
The more olives, the better.
It's a big portion.
It is a big portion,
but the best part is,
you can take some home.
WOMAN:
I love walking into this place.
It's just -- kind of feel like
home when I come here.
And here's the deal --
In a mom-and-pop joint,
it's all that energy
and all that love
and family participation
that really makes it so great.
I believe it. Thanks.
Great job, man.
Great job.
FIERI: Up next, a unique stop
in Eugene, Oregon...
That's awesome.
...making outrageous eats...
Very impressed.
...without meat.
I would challenge anybody
to try that and tell me
that they don't dig it.
So, "Triple D" has been
on the air for over 7 1/2 years,
over 21 seasons,
and we have visited
over 800 locations.
We've had a lot of firsts --
first burger joint,
barbecue joint, taco joint,
you name it.
The list goes on and on.
I got a new first for you.
We're here in Eugene, Oregon,
to check out
an all-vegan restaurant.
This is Cornbread Cafe.
Fish and chips, table 2.
It's wonderful,
Southern-style comfort food.
Barbecue plate, table 3.
Everything is really yummy.
If you weren't a vegan
and you came in here,
I think you'd see
a lot of the similar items
that you see
at most comfort-food diners.
FIERI:
Which is no accident.
What I like to do
is veganize traditional recipes.
Since 2011, owner Sheree Walters
has been serving up
those favorites
in a funky '50s building.
Was it an old diner?
It was a drive-in.
So, you wanted
a diner feeling...
Yep.
...but you wanted
to make it vegan.
Mm-hmm.
WOMAN: I'm a meat-eater,
and this is a place
that I've never noticed
that I am not eating meat.
Eugenewich up, table 1.
The Eugenewich
is their signature sandwich.
It's a big slab
of fried, flavorful tofu
with haystack onions.
It's delicious.
We're gonna make Southern-fried
tofu for our Eugenewich.
All right, so,
let's get into this.
How many pounds of tofu
do you guys think you
go through in a week?
Give or take, 350 pounds.
A lot of tofu.
We're gonna line it
on the sheet tray...
bake it for about 14 minutes
in a 350-degree oven.
All right, so, we've got
our tofu that is cooled down.
Okay.
And we're ready to start
making the dredge.
Unsweetened soy milk.
Apple cider vinegar.
Little hot sauce.
And the hot sauce.
So, this is making
our buttermilk.
Yep.
All right,
we're gonna season the flour.
Yep. Baking powder.
Great. Salt.
And sea salt
and poultry seasoning,
black pepper,
and celery seed.
And then I just get my hands
in there and mix it up.
Let me see the magic.
[ Chuckles ]
So, it goes
into the buttermilk.
Dredge them through.
Yep.
Back into the buttermilk.
And a dredge.
You get a nice coating on this.
And that goes in the fryer
for about two minutes.
We're gonna fry all this
and build a sandwich.
All right.
Then I put on
the Daiya tapioca cheese.
Take a grilled bun.
This is our Eugenewich sauce
that we made with our house-made
barbecue sauce and vegan mayo.
And lettuce and tomato,
our Southern-fried
tofu patty,
and this is
our carrot bacon.
Interesting.
Our haystack onions,
then we're gonna pair that
with our home fries.
Here you go, "Triple D" --
vegan.
That's great.
It's got texture.
It's got chew.
The barbecue sauce
is out of bounds.
The haystack fries --
that makes it fly.
I don't get anything like,
"Ohh, that's tofu."
[ Laughs ]
I mean,
I would challenge anybody
that says they don't like
vegan food
to try that and tell me
that they don't dig it.
Nice job.
Thank you.
You got the crispiness
of the tofu.
It has a sweetness to it.
It has a smokiness.
So, this is Chef Preston,
owns one of the best
sushi restaurants
that you'll find
here in the Eugene area.
Tell me
what you think, Chef.
Texture is just crispy
and perfect.
I can feel the owner's passion
in the food.
Hot Thing, no veggies,
and a Reuben, table 5.
Where did you
learn to cook?
I learned to cook
from my grandma.
Very nice.
Grandma was vegan?
A vegetarian
for 60-plus years.
No! Really?
Yep.
That's awesome.
I got the frozen
peanut butter pie.
Oh, boy!
FIERI: And it looks like
dessert's also been handed down.
The frozen peanut butter pie
is just awesome.
It's almost like a frozen
peanut butter cup.
We're going to make
our frozen peanut butter pie.
Got vegan cream cheese.
We'll beat that.
Creamy peanut butter here.
So, we're gonna alternate
a few times
between the soy milk
and powdered sugar.
You want me to sprinkle?
Yeah.
All right,
here's our vegan whipped cream.
Into the springform pan.
I'm gonna drizzle
chocolate sauce.
Do a little swirly.
Very cool.
Goes into the freezer
for two hours.
Peanut butter pie, Guy.
It's just a really
excellent balance
of flavor and texture,
kind of a cross
between a cheesecake
and an ice cream pie.
That right there
has a savory component to it,
like with the peanuts.
Not overly sweet
by any means.
It's awesome.
It really is.
WOMAN: It's thick.
It's rich.
It's a perfect combination
of peanut butter and chocolate.
In fact,
I would work here for free
just to learn
how to do what they do.
You could have named it
"Funkalicious."
I'm very impressed.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Very proud of you.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
That's good.
[ Whistling ]
Uh, hey, Johnny?
I need the metal container
with the flour in it
for the table.
[ Laughter ]