Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
What in the wild, wild world
of sports is going on here?
...the Camaro's headed east...
Let me get in.
...for a big taste
of Baltimore, Maryland.
One of our favorite
"Triple D" towns.
First...
That is no fakin' bacon
right there.
...a place going
farm-to-table...
This is what everybody
is looking for.
...getting meticulous
with the meat.
I'm a freak
for the cheek.
Then across town...
Looks like me dancing.
...a family-owned
local legend...
That's outrageous.
...cooking up
coastal classics.
I come to Maryland, I want the
bomb crab cakes, you deliver.
And in the Fell's Point
neighborhood...
Let's get after this.
...a joint dishing out
killer pizza...
Can't go wrong.
...alongside a wild vibe.
This is like you said,
"One day I'm gonna put up
all cool skateboard stuff
and have beer, and all my
friends can come over."
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
I'm here in Baltimore, a town
known for a lot of things.
Let's see, you got
the Super Bowl champ Ravens,
you got the Orioles,
you got the Inner Harbor,
you got my new restaurant,
Guy's Baltimore,
in the Horseshoe Casino,
but do you really think about
this town for a farm-to-table?
Well, you will
after you visit this joint.
This is Clementine.
Comfort food on steroids.
Burger up!
Like a nice neighborhood
sort of place.
FIERI:
Exactly the kind of place chef
and owner Winston Blick wanted
when he opened this joint
in '08.
Tell me about the name
Winston.
That's an inherited name
from my grandfather.
My mother was supposed to
be Winston Page.
That would have
been awkward.
She's Winifred Page.
Winnie's a great name. I've got
a good friend named Winnie.
Hi, Winnie.
What kind of restaurant
is Clementine?
Primarily farm-to-table.
He really respects the meat.
It is processed and aged
and cured in-house.
Meatloaf up!
The bacon-wrapped meatloaf
is awesome.
WOMAN: The bacon grease
drips into the meatloaf.
It's delicious.
I assume you're gonna make
your own bacon.
Exactly.
That's a good-looking pig.
We are first gonna trim away
some of what we don't need.
We're gonna use all of it,
but we're not gonna be using it
for the pork belly.
Now we're gonna
give it a...
Dry rub.
Brown sugar.
Kosher salt.
Cinnamon.
Ground glove.
Cayenne.
Ground black pepper.
And some curing salt.
Let the dry rub sit on there
for a week?
Yep.
And then what's gonna happen
when this comes out?
We smoke it.
What kind of wood
we smoking it with?
Usually alder.
Let's get in the meatloaf.
We begin with a panade,
which is bread and milk.
Ground chuck.
Ground brisket.
Ground short rib --
a coarse grind.
Little textural difference.
Exactly.
One egg
per pound of meat.
Good little ratio.
And the sweated mirepoix.
Mirepoix.
Smoked paprika.
Cumin.
Chili powder.
Worcestershire sauce.
Coarse ground pepper.
Kosher salt.
And mix.
That's it right there.
We are gonna slice bacon.
Mmm. I can smell the smoke
on that already.
There we go.
Doctor.
And then
we lay out our bacon.
That is no fakin' bacon
right there.
Then we apply
the meatloaf mixture.
Make sort of a log.
That's it.
Now we're gonna wrap it up.
Now we're done. Go in the oven.
What temp?
350, 45 minutes.
Bring it out,
let it cool?
Yes.
Let it congeal.
Slice it in portions, and how
do we reheat it for service?
We reheat it
on a sizzle platter.
What are we
gonna serve it with?
Start with mashed potatoes
with smoked Gouda cheese...
greens as in kale.
Look at that.
That is the meatloaf.
That's a healthy portion
there.
And a little gravy.
Mushroom, rye whiskey,
and a little cream.
Bacon wrapped meatloaf.
The greens are out of bounds.
And I mean outrageous.
Mmm. The mashed potatoes
are on point.
This is fantastic.
Mmm.
And the meatloaf is up there
in the best meatloafs I've had.
You let that bacon
just cook through,
really bring that flavor in.
That just takes you home.
I mean, that is just real good,
simple comfort food
done incredibly well.
I appreciate it.
Seriously, man.
I truly appreciate it.
The bomb.
The bacon wrapped around it
makes it really moist and juicy.
And taste exactly
like it should.
MAN:
The savory aspects of the bacon
tied into the sweetness
of the meatloaf
just makes it really excellent.
I got to start a show called,
like, "The Baltimore All-Stars."
To kick it off,
my buddies Bob and Donna,
who have the best pit beef,
in my opinion -- Chaps Pit Beef.
How many years ago
did we shoot "Triple D" there?
2008.
So out of a place
that serves primarily meat,
you're down here
having meatloaf.
How is it?
It's delicious.
Couldn't do any better.
So are the greens.
The greens are the bomb.
Of course,
you know this character,
the wonderful Sofia
from Sip & Bite.
One of the craziest
that you'll find in Baltimore,
you see this farm-to-table
attitude in this place.
You see more of that happening
in Baltimore?
Yes, a lot more organic
and more locally grown.
I think Baltimore's
becoming a food destination.
We hope so.
Winston is a person with a lot
of integrity about his food,
and that's why we eat here.
FIERI:
Now, when we come back,
chef has got a pig treat for us
made out of the cheeks.
Asian-braised pork cheeks.
Might be
one of my favorite cuts.
Another home run.
You guys ready for this?
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Baltimore, Maryland,
one of our favorite
"Triple D" towns
that you can find
with Chef Winston,
who has this funky joint
called Clementine.
This place is one of
the cornerstones of
this neighborhood.
The vibe
is comfortable and friendly.
The food is outstanding here.
From his charcuterie room
to making his own bacon
to taking now the cheeks
from the head of the hog.
One of my favorite
cuts of pork.
Pork cheeks up!
It's a little sweet,
it's a little savory.
It's an extremely comforting
dish to me.
What we have
is the head of a hog.
It's a cheeky fellow.
One of the most flavorful
and lean cuts are the cheeks.
That's the cheek.
I'm a freak
for the cheek.
We're gonna add black pepper.
Chopped garlic.
Curing salt.
Keep it a little pink.
Palm sugar.
And kosher salt.
And how long are we
gonna let this cure?
Overnight.
So the cheeks have had their day
to sit there with the rub.
We add Kaffir lime leaves.
Bruise them some just to get
some more fragrance out of them.
Lemongrass.
Minced garlic.
Black peppercorn.
Lots of it.
I like that.
Chinese cooking wine.
Sweet soy sauce.
I'm a huge sweet soy fan.
And last but not least...
The pork stock.
Just about halfway up.
350, 2 1/2 hours.
Okay, let's do it.
Coconut rice, bok choy,
and baby carrots.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
Just falling apart.
Little green onion
and cilantro.
Pork cheeks.
Not just any pork cheeks.
Sir Winston.
Look how lean
that cheek is.
You get the richness
of this heritage pork...
...to come out kissed
with the lemongrass,
kissed
with the Kaffir lime,
done ever so lightly with
a little bit of the curing
that you gave it.
I mean, just spot-on.
And the cheek is just delicate,
falls apart,
you taste the flavor,
the veggies are fresh.
All the aspects
are just done
with such regard
for the end result.
Outstanding. Great job.
I appreciate that.
They're melt-in-your-mouth
tender, cooked perfectly.
Delicious.
I can tell from these
pork cheeks that this
was a happy pig.
This was a happy pig.
I can tell.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah. Big smile.
WOMAN: It's groaningly good,
it's foot-thumping good,
and sometimes
they hit Meg Ryan good.
I mean, this is a gift
to Baltimore
and the surrounding area.
This is what everybody
is looking for.
It's that
kind of outrageous.
Awesome job.
I appreciate that.
I really appreciate it.
Seriously, man.
Awesome job.
FIERI: Coming up
in Southeast Baltimore...
I've got to watch this
petite dancer's figure.
...the landmark
seafood emporium...
That gives me goose bumps.
...where crab is truly king.
That's how big it is?
Like crab meatloaf?
I'm here in Baltimore, Maryland,
about 10 minutes from downtown
to check out a joint
where a family lives
on the second floor --
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm getting confused.
That was 40 years ago.
Now they've turned it into
a super-successful
seafood restaurant
that seats over 500 people,
and the crab cakes are the bomb!
This is Jimmy's Famous Seafood.
Seafood Ecstasy up!
Their seafood
has always been top-notch.
It's a family business.
The recipes have
been carried on for
a number of years.
FIERI: Those recipes
come from Jimmy Minidakis,
who opened this place in 1974,
raising his family
on the second floor.
And since his passing,
his sons and wife, Foula,
are carrying on his legacy.
Got mussels up!
It's a blessing
to carry one man's dream
that started with nothing.
You're the chef?
Yes.
You're the manager,
front of the house,
and you're the boss.
Backbone.
I know who the boss is.
Crab cake up!
MAN: It's always worth a trip
to come down to East Baltimore
and have a Jimmy's crab cake.
The crab cake is literally
the size of a baseball.
All lump, no filling.
Now, whose recipe is this?
Father's.
So we're gonna take about 30
eggs, give them a little whisk.
Next up -- mayonnaise.
I'll mix that up.
We're gonna go with
our Worcestershire Sauce.
Worcestershire.
Okay.
Black pepper.
Rock salt.
Okay.
House seasoning.
Not too much.
Dry mustard.
Wet mustard.
And next up?
Now we're ready to start making
the crab cakes.
The crab is local from
the eastern shore of Maryland.
So what goes first?
First, couple ladles
of the sauce.
Chopped bread crumbs.
Parsley.
Crabmeat.
By weight, this is 95% crab,
5% binding ingredient.
That's outrageous.
Now we're gonna make the crab
cakes into 8-ounce portions.
That's how big it is?
What is it, like crab meatloaf?
Pretty much.
Put our house seasoning on top
and a little bit of butter.
How we gonna cook it?
350 degrees,
about 15 minutes.
Here's our crab cake.
How many come with an order?
One or two.
Let's just do one.
I've got to watch this
petite dancer's figure.
We're gonna serve it with
our house-made crackers.
Tartar sauce.
Our cocktail sauce.
That's ridiculous.
Look at the size of that lump?
It doesn't need to be
dipped in anything.
Here's the deal, bro.
[ Crunches ]
There's places
that you go to
'cause they've been around
forever.
This is
that kind of place.
I come to Maryland, I want the
bomb crab cakes, you deliver.
Thanks, bro.
Nice job.
The outside
is absolutely crispy,
and then you prick into it,
and it's nothing but crabmeat.
Crab cake up!
MAN: I'm just spoiled by
the crab cake here.
I cannot get a crab cake
anywhere else.
So let's talk about Jimmy
for a second.
How proud is your dad?
I hope he's very proud.
Very proud.
Is this the dream
he told you about
when you guys
were married?
Oh, he was definitely
ahead of his time.
That gives me goose bumps.
MAN:
It's a family environment, man.
When you come here,
you just feel welcome.
The food's unbelievable.
There's nothing
that you can order on the menu
that you'll be displeased with.
Soft Crab Po'Boy up!
Absolutely delicious.
The crab is huge.
It has a nice, spicy mustard
on it.
Next up?
Soft crab sandwich.
I just have to
let you know something.
I just came in here to see how
authentic things really were,
so I had to bring in
a surprise guest.
All right, this is my executive
chef from Johnny Garlic's
in California,
Chef Jeff Poetzel.
Now,
Jeff is from this area.
I had to get in on it.
[ Whistles ]
Looks like me dancing.
We got to do
a little cleaning?
Yep.
And that's all she wrote.
That's it.
What's the next step?
Eggs, buttermilk.
Just a simple dredge
and pan-fry it.
Clarified butter?
Yes, sir.
Well, we have Johns Hopkins
in the area, so we're good.
Two minutes on each side.
Nice, crispy,
golden brown.
Okay.
Dress with a little
Chesapeake mustard.
Fresh lettuce.
Fresh tomato.
Put the crab
right on there.
Wow.
Grab our fries.
Little Chesapeake mustard
to finish it off again.
Let me get in here.
Here we go.
All right.
Mmm. Wow.
It's that mustard
with the mustard that makes it.
The crab is so fresh,
the batter is so light,
light roll with just
a bit of texture to it.
Jeff, how does it rate,
1 to 10?
10. It would be 11
if there was 11 on the dial.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
The seasoning
is what makes the sandwich.
I've tried not to make a mess,
but it's very hard,
'cause it's so good, you just
want to keep digging in.
It's worth its weight in gold.
[ Chuckles ]
Jimmy's -- It's a legacy.
They've gone down in history
in Baltimore.
A lot of family love,
a lot of family respect.
You guys are doing
a phenomenal job.
It's been
an awesome experience.
Grazie.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Up next on our Baltimore tour...
I like this.
...a skate punk hangout
in Upper Fell's Point...
That's exactly
what this is.
...turning out
some tasty tricks.
At a funky joint like this?
Dynamite.
So I'm here in Upper Fell's
Point in Baltimore, Maryland,
just a couple blocks
from the harbor,
where a dude that's a big
skateboard and punk-rock fan
has taken
an old-school local bar
and turned it into kind of
like a Neapolitan pizzeria,
except he calls it
a "Baltipolitan" pizzeria.
This is Johnny Rad's.
[ Sizzling ]
Two orders
of risotto balls up.
Little bit more upscale
as far as the food goes
than you would expect
at a skater joint.
Salty caramel
bread pudding.
The vibe here is awesome.
We have old skate guys,
a lot of tattooers come in here.
FIERI: Which also pretty much
describes Rich Pugh,
the dude who started this joint
back in 2010.
Why Johnny Rad's?
It's a name
of a fictional character
in an old skateboard movie
from 1987.
Were you in the restaurant
business before this?
Not at all.
I started making pizza at home.
And taught himself
to master the pie.
Now he's got Chef Grayson Reeder
cranking out his recipes.
I love the pizza here.
There's a lot of vegetarian
options -- the Trainwreck.
Got a large Trainwreck --
Table 6.
[ Bell dings ]
It's got olives
and baby spinach.
Marinara sauce,
really crispy dough.
Holy...
What in the wild, wild world
of sports is going on here?
That is huge!
How much dough do you make?
We go through about two or three
batches a day.
Let's get after this.
All right.
First we're gonna put
our water in the bowl.
Next we're gonna add
our secret ingredient,
which is actually cola.
Cola's in.
Now we're gonna add
the bloomed yeast.
Flour. Kosher salt.
Lot of salt.
We're gonna let it mix
for about three minutes.
All right, so now we're gonna
add our extra virgin olive oil.
There you go.
Yeah.
We're gonna let that mix
for another 15 minutes.
Now we're gonna
come out of the bowl.
FIERI:
Want me to hold the bucket?
There we go.
Get in there.
17 1/2 ounces.
Correct?
Yeah.
You ever seen
this maneuver?
Yep, yeah.
Look at that, huh?
It's perfect.
Beautiful.
We brush the top
of the dough balls
with extra virgin olive oil.
Doughs proof 24 hours.
Here we go.
Two ladles of red sauce.
It's a very light amount
of sauce.
Yeah.
Next goes the Spinach.
Little bit of mushroom.
And now we have black olives.
These are
fresh mozzarella balls.
A little bit of
extra virgin olive oil.
And this is
the Trainwreck.
In the oven, 650.
About 6 minutes.
Good-looking pie.
[ Sniffs ]
Smell that yeast.
Now we're gonna add
a little bit of salt.
Little bit
of Asiago cheese.
Gonna cut it.
And that's all she wrote.
That's all she wrote.
Good-looking crust.
The crust is nice and thin.
Light and airy,
not doughy and heavy.
You do get a little bit
of that cola in there.
Get a little bit
of that carbo.
But you didn't overdo it
with too much ingredients.
[ Crunching ]
Got great balance.
Love the fresh mozzarella.
That's a nice slice.
Can't go wrong.
At a funky joint like this?
Dynamite.
WOMAN:
Ingredients are really fresh.
I like the crust.
It's nice and chewy
but crispy at the same time.
A good amount of toppings on it
but not too much.
This is totally my scene.
There's always good music
playing.
There's good videos on the TV.
Has some cool video games
over in the side room.
I come here just exclusively
for Skee-ball.
And then really good food,
as well.
MAN: You can get burgers,
you can get appetizers
like the risotto balls.
Gooey on the inside,
crispy on the outside,
and the perfect pre-pizza snack.
All right,
let's get after this.
So risotto balls.
Little bit of canola oil.
Go in with some mushrooms.
Go in with
a little yellow onion.
Veggie seasoning.
Little veggie seasoning?
Little bit of kosher salt.
Little bit of pepper.
Sauté that out
for three or four minutes.
We're gonna add
our arborio rice.
Let that
get a little toasted.
White wine?
Whole lot of white wine.
Whole milk.
Let this cook down...
About 15 minutes.
We're gonna add the Caesar Blend
cheese, a little heavy cream.
After the risotto cooks
for about 15, 20 minutes,
we add it to a hotel pan
to cool in the walk-in.
There we go.
The white wine in that --
gangster.
You didn't overcook it.
So we're gonna scoop, put a
little divot in the center.
[ Chuckles ]
Add some cheese.
A little mozzarella cheese
surprise.
Drop in Italian breadcrumb.
How many come with an order?
Six.
I like this.
Risotto balls
are all finished.
And what kind of sauce
we serving them with?
Our pizza sauce.
It's good risotto
just by itself.
Then you add a little bit
of mozzarella cheese in it.
Lightly fried.
Not even really fried --
just warming it.
You get that wine and mushroom
flavor coming through
from the risotto.
Pizza sauce -- It's a nice,
bright, fresh tomato flavor.
Yeah.
That's a nice, simple
Arancini rice ball --
whatever you call it.
Well done, brother.
The chef makes the risotto
at perfect al dente,
and so you have this combination
of textures.
Excellent for soaking up the
drinks that you'll be consuming.
You've watched Food Network,
you know "Ace of Cakes" original
Mary here.
What is it about Johnny Rad's
that is so cool?
MARY:
Great food, great people.
I'm friends with, like,
half of the staff, and...
You're friends with
half the country.
Yeah, that's true.
This is like when we were kids
and you said,
"One day I'm gonna put up
all cool skateboard stuff
and play really awesome music
and make pizza and have beer,
and all my friends
can come over."
I couldn't have said it
better myself.
That's exactly
what this is.
So, that's it for this road
trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ As Darth Vader ]
Luke, I am your father.
[ Laughter ]