Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoa!
...we're reeling in
some fresh fish...
That's the freshest experience
you can get.
...and dishing out
some funky chicken...
Winner, winner,
chicken-wing dinner.
...in Eugene, Oregon...
Fishermen are cool.
...a hook-to-table market...
This is a full seafood
culinary experience.
...cooking everything
from crab to crawfish.
ROGERS: You got to keep
the customers happy.
They won't go home.
In Des Moines, Iowa...
[ Whistles ]
...a legit
South American chef...
Authentic Ecuadorian
scratch-made, man.
...bringing his homeland
to the Heartland.
So, you ship corn into Iowa?
Yeah.
Then, we're headed
across town...
What, the whole coop
come with this order?
...to check out
an award-winning barbecue duo...
You are the real deal.
...smoking up their meat
for the masses.
That's a big Ferris wheel
in Flavortown.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here in Eugene, Oregon,
home of the Ducks,
University of Oregon.
Now, what else can you expect
when you come to Eugene,
an hour and a half
off the coast of Oregon?
Exactly --
great fresh seafood.
That's because they got this
joint -- Fisherman's Market.
Every time I come in here,
they'll be bringing
fresh fish in,
you know, whether it's gonna be
salmon or albacore, halibut.
They're live right there,
they cook them right there,
and they serve it right here,
and I eat it.
Ryan --
He just is an expert on fish.
FIERI: That's because
Ryan Rogers is the real deal,
hard-core fishing in Alaska
for decades
while running this joint
since '97.
All the fish that's here
is coming from?
Mostly all from Oregon.
You have all your buddies
and all the hookups and --
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
It's like
it was swimming yesterday.
Some of it still is.
See the crab in the crab tank,
and then they cook it up
for you fresh.
It's just amazing.
Crab dinner with fries and slaw.
They cook the crab in a crab pot
right out the front door.
Can't get any fresher.
Give me the rundown, man.
Okay. So, we got our pot
full of hot water.
We add salt to make it
about the same as the ocean.
So, these are
live Dungeness.
Live.
Where are these
coming from?
Off of our boat
out in Newport.
So, we like to put them in
upside down,
'cause then the claws
come in like this.
You put them in backwards,
the claws go like that,
and they drop them.
And how long
do they take to cook?
Anywhere from
25 to 45 minutes.
Then what's gonna happen?
You're gonna get some ice
in the cooling tank,
chill them down
as fast as we can.
How many pounds of crab
is that right now?
That's about 50.
We can do 100 at a time.
Wow.
I'm gonna say we're gonna go
for an electric winch
one of these days.
This is a huge improvement.
We used to do them
one at a time by hand.
Let them all cool down.
Stop the cooking process.
Yep.
FIERI:
And while those guys chill,
well, it's time
to slay some slaw.
This is our cilantro lime
dressing for our coleslaw.
First, we put in salt,
jalapeño.
A small amount of garlic.
Get that all mixed up.
Help me out there.
Lime juice.
Olive oil.
Cilantro.
Now we're gonna make
the slaw.
Pour that in for us,
and we'll get her done.
Revitalize the palate.
Like the tang?
That's like "whoo" tang.
[ Laughs ]
Heat the crab back up
a little bit.
Clean it first.
Whoa!
Is this like
speed crab cleaning?
[ Grunting ]
Okay.
We're ready for crab.
Bring it.
All right.
Whoa! It's hot.
A little warm for you?
But that is hot crab.
That's outrageous.
Without question,
the most
seafood-flavored crab...
Right.
...really, I think,
has to be the Dungeness.
Some lemon juice.
I'll take a little dip
in some butter.
That slaw...
Nice crunch.
Really refreshes the palate.
That's the freshest experience
you can get.
WOMAN: It's juicy.
It's succulent.
You don't even need the butter,
it's so wonderful.
MAN:
Dungeness crab dinner.
Dungeness crab
is especially sweet.
And it's got such a
really good flavor. You
can't get it fresher.
WOMAN #2:
I like the Fisherman's Market
because there's
just nothing else like it.
It's extremely unique.
FIERI:
Kind of a crazy place.
You got
tanks making noise and coolers,
people buying fish,
dudes cooking right there.
It's different food that you
can get from anywhere else.
FIERI: You can get fish and
chips with any kind of fish?
Any kind of fish.
Seriously?
Yeah.
WOMAN: You can't get bored.
You can always
try something new.
The Cajun crawfish pie.
FIERI: Here's the deal.
Hanging out at Fisherman's
Market in Eugene, Oregon.
What are we gonna make
when we come back?
Crawfish pie.
Cajun crawfish pie.
This guy's off the hook.
Don't touch any of this.
[ Laughs ]
Welcome back.
"Triple D."
In a little bit
of a food coma
at the Fisherman's Market
in Eugene, Oregon.
Dungeness crab done simply,
but outstanding.
It literally
has been a mess.
But I'm gonna stop,
because you promised me
real crawfish pie.
Cajun crawfish pie.
Cajun crawfish pie?
The Cajun crawfish pie
is really good.
It's really unusual.
The flavor's incredible.
It reminds me of New Orleans.
And how are we
gonna start this off?
We're gonna purge the crawfish,
get them cleaned up.
Wow.
Those are some monsters.
So, these are farm-raised?
No.
No. These are wild.
No? These are wild-caught?
Yeah. They come out
of clean lakes, clean streams.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Next step?
Put them
in the boiling water.
Seasoned lightly.
Salted water.
How long
we gonna let them go?
ROGERS:
About five minutes.
Okay. They're done.
We'll crack them,
peel them,
harvest all the meat,
then make the pie?
We're gonna make
the filling.
Dump the butter in.
So, just a small, petite amount
of butter -- 5 pounds.
Green pepper,
diced onion...
red pepper, celery.
Let the vegetables sweat.
Next step?
Ready for our spices.
We got salt, pepper,
granulated onion.
Granulated garlic,
some thyme.
Cayenne.
Paprika.
And this is the weird one.
Brown sugar?
You got it.
All right. So, we'll let
this all come together.
And what are we gonna
tighten it up with?
So, we put our flour
with flavor in.
We add some things to it -- a
little garlic, a little pepper.
You got yourself
a little roux.
Get our potatoes in
and the crawfish.
Seriously? That much?
Nice, big pieces.
Wow!
Meaty pie.
You got to keep
the customers happy.
They won't go home.
[ Laughs ]
That's how much heavy cream
we're putting in?
What's wrong with that?
5 pounds of butter
and a thimble
of heavy cream.
We'll let that simmer
till it's all warm.
And then, we're gonna start
making these.
We're gonna start
filling the pies.
Oh, that is ridiculous.
You're gonna be sending me that
for Christmas.
All right.
In the oven how long?
About 20 minutes.
We got lots of beers to drink
while you wait.
Pssh!
Fishermen are cool.
Time for pie.
What's that
you're putting on top?
Sour cream.
And what do you have over here
on the salad?
We got smoked salmon,
house salad.
Dude, that's outrageous!
You smoke this in-house?
Of course.
You're so gangster.
Let's look at this.
Mmm.
Great crust.
Not soupy.
Not too thick.
Tender.
They're as tender
and succulent,
and the texture of them
is awesome.
I didn't know about the
sour-cream thing you were
doing, but it's excellent.
This is crazy, man.
Mmm.
It's perfect.
Just enough spice
to have a little kick.
This is to die for.
It's so flaky.
It just can't get any fresher
unless you caught it yourself.
If I'm hungry, I just say,
"We're going here."
This is a full seafood
culinary experience --
from the live tanks
to the fresh seafood market,
doing the food,
dishes like that.
How much do you
think we can fit in
the back of that car?
You know, I'm only about eight
hours away from my town.
Ice it up.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up, a barbecue
joint in Des Moines, Iowa...
Delicious.
...taking their secrets
from competition...
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
Use your competition fingers.
...and serving them
straight out of the kitchen.
No wonder
you win all the time.
So, I'm here
in Des Moines, Iowa.
I say Iowa, what do you think?
Exactly -- pork.
I say pork, what do you think?
Uh-huh. Barbecue.
I say Des Moines, Iowa,
I say pork, I think barbecue,
and I think about that team
that's won almost every
barbecue competition there is,
and they've got a restaurant.
That's right.
This is Smokey D's.
WARTH:
Barbecue nachos with pork.
The food here is phenomenal.
Half rack, bean, and mac.
It is a bonanza
of barbecue bliss.
FIERI:
Courtesy of champion barbecuers
Darren Warth and Shad Kirton --
two dudes
who opened this joint in 2010.
And at 11,000 square feet,
well, I'm calling it
the swine coliseum.
FIERI: This is nuts!
Three full-blown smokers,
24/7.
WARTH: 24/7.
[ Laughs ] That's a big Ferris
wheel in Flavortown.
The brisket, pork.
The ribs are crazy.
And don't forget
about the chicken.
WOMAN:
Asian smoked wings.
They've got a real nice
smoke flavor to them,
and then they deep fry them.
They've got a nice crunch
at the end.
Winner, winner,
chicken-wing dinner.
[ Laughs ]
So, Doctor, hit it up.
Yep.
Let's make a rub.
Okay. We're gonna do
sugar, salt, brown sugar,
chili powder,
black pepper, paprika.
I like the way you do it.
Onion powder.
Bring it.
Garlic powder, a little cumin,
Cayenne pepper.
Gonna mix it up.
We're gonna take wings,
dump them in the bowl.
A little rub on top.
What kind of wood
are we going on?
Everything's cherry here.
Everything's cherry out here?
Okay. To the smoker.
Okay.
How long will it be
in the smoker?
About an hour
and 15 minutes.
All right.
So, the wings are down.
Now it's time for the?
Asian glaze.
I got the hoisin sauce,
teriyaki,
honey,
white balsamic vinegar.
We're going Asian,
and you went Italian.
Exactly.
No rice-wine vinegar?
It's a barbecue place.
Sriracha,
red-pepper flake.
Whoa!
Okay.
So, we let this come together.
Delicious.
Okay. Wings done?
Wings are done.
Over to the fryer.
Frying them at the end.
Put a little crisp on them.
A little sauce on there.
Stand back.
What kind of sauce
do you serve with this?
A little
blue cheese dressing.
What, the whole coop
come with this order?
The whole coop.
Mmm.
Dynamite.
And I like that you cook
your wing crispy.
Mmm.
It's fantastic.
Cherrywood
plays in perfect.
Great spice.
Nice balance.
Subtle, not overdone.
Great job, brother.
Great job.
Thanks.
WOMAN: Asian smoked wings.
The smoked wings
are really juicy, really tender.
I love the Asian glaze sauce.
It's fantastic.
You can see why they get awards
for their food.
WOMAN #2: There are a lot
of trophies around here.
You know you're getting
something good.
I'm really impressed
not only to see you in
the barbecue-competition circuit
and how well you've done,
but to see that you guys
are the real deal
running your restaurant,
making great food.
FIERI: Which means cooking up
more than just 'cue.
Apple dumpling.
The apple dumpling
is to die for.
Just melts in your mouth.
It's even better
than my -- my grandmother's.
What are we on to now,
brother?
The apple dumpling.
[ Whistles ]
Core the apples,
peel the apples.
How's that?
Perfect.
That looks good?
Great.
[ Chuckles ]
Now we got to do another one,
'cause you ate that one.
You don't know
about an apple peeler,
the automated ones?
Yeah, we know about it.
We're trying
to employ people here.
Let's make
the pastry dough.
This should be
interesting.
Yeah.
You look like
a pastry-dough guy to me.
You might want
to stand back.
I bet I do.
Okay. Flour, salt.
There you go. Whoo.
Lard, cold butter.
Mixed together.
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
You pump it up.
Use your
competition fingers.
[ Laughs ]
Little water.
You're gonna be mixing it
together as I do it?
Yeah, yeah.
There we go.
We're gonna wrap it up,
and we're gonna put
it in the refrigerator,
let it sit overnight.
Okay. The dough
had a chance to rest.
We're gonna roll out
the dough,
and we're gonna cut it
in six.
Now we're gonna wrap
the apple dumplings.
Little butter.
Brown sugar?
Brown sugar.
Stuff it tight.
Right in the hole.
Cinnamon.
Cinna-minna-mon.
We love cinnamon.
[ Whistles ]
Snowing in Flavortown.
Then, we're gonna wrap it.
And that's it? Really?
Form it.
In the pan.
What's the last piece?
And we're gonna do
a little dumpling sauce.
And what is
in the dumpling sauce?
A little water, sugar,
butter, vanilla.
How long
we gonna bake that off at?
375 for about 35 minutes.
Got it.
Apple dumpling.
This is money.
Boy, you get that tang.
You get a little bit
of the crunch of the dough.
Then you get some
of the soft dough
that's cooked in the syrup
the entire time.
"Apple Dumpling Gang
Rides Again."
This rocks.
WOMAN:
Here's the apple dumpling.
A little tartness,
a little sweetness.
It's just
the perfect combination.
Just like a little taste
of heaven. [ Laughs ]
Tenderloin with fries.
It's just really
a wonderful experience.
Order up in the window.
I love this place.
You have got a real nice
variety on your menu,
and the food's legit, man.
You are the real deal.
Thank you.
No wonder
you win all the time.
FIERI: Up next, one more
Des Moines destination...
Beautiful.
...for an Ecuadorian feast...
I mean, what's not to love
about that?
...that's bringing on the heat.
Whoa! That's hot!
MIRANDA: Can you taste
the jalapeño?
No! No, no, no, no.
I'm here
in West Des Moines, Iowa,
on a warm summer day
right off the 235 freeway.
And of all places,
I'm in a strip mall,
'cause I hear they're serving up
the bomb Ecuadorian food.
This is Mi Patria.
Lomo saltado, table one.
It's like
a mom-and-pop shop here.
Got churrasco
in the window.
Finding this restaurant
here in Des Moines is great.
It's a hidden gem.
FIERI:
This South American treasure
is owned by Chef Cesar Miranda,
who's been serving up
a taste of Ecuador since 2011.
WOMAN:
It's just from the heart.
That's what I love
the most about it.
Hornado con mote.
I love the pork.
That's one of my favorites.
WOMAN #2: There are
so many distinct flavors,
but they all blend together
so well.
It just makes
your taste buds dance.
FIERI: All right. So,
what are we gonna make, man?
We're gonna make
our hornado con mote,
which means pulled pork
with Ecuadorian white hominy.
Okay.
Let's make the pork.
Season first with salt.
Got it.
And our house suiza we make
with red onion, garlic,
oregano, cumin,
salt, and water.
Then, we add
our achiote oil.
It's gonna give it
some color.
Water.
We're gonna cover it
with plastic and foil.
How long we gonna cook this?
4 1/2 hours.
At what temp?
Gotcha.
350.
[ Whistles ]
That plastic wrap with the foil
just locks in all that steam
and really cooks
that meat down.
Yeah.
We shred this.
We drop it.
Now, what will happen
after we shred it?
We got a little bit
of achiote oil in it,
our pork fat,
our white hominy,
and season it with salt.
So, where do you get
this big, fat corn from?
From Ecuador.
So, you ship corn into Iowa?
Yeah.
Now we're gonna
put this together?
Yeah. Little white rice,
lettuce, our salad.
Okay.
Our corn.
We're gonna add
our pulled pork,
top it
with a potato patty.
And that just goes
right up on top?
Right on top.
The meat is super-tender,
but a lot of uniqueness to it.
Everything's done perfectly.
The hominy is spot-on.
You know, get the acid
out of the salad.
Then you get
the nuttiness of the corn.
But you put all of that together
in this perfect bite.
That's outrageous.
It's very flavorful
and moist and tender.
You can just pull it apart
with a fork.
It melts in your mouth.
[ Laughs ] It's heaven.
It's good stuff.
"Mi Patria" means?
"My homeland." Yes.
"My homeland."
How do you explain
Ecuadorian food?
Flavorful,
colorful, unique.
Got empanadas
in the window.
FIERI: Where you from?
Ecuador.
How close is this to home?
The same.
This could be in Ecuador?
Yeah, yeah.
MIRANDA:
Arroz con pollo is ready.
Oh, this is my guilty
pleasure right here.
It's amazing how they've
taken chicken and rice
and turned it
into something super-special.
We're gonna cook our chicken
for our arroz con pollo.
Fire it up.
First, we got
the whole chicken.
Put them
in the boiling water.
Oh, that's it?
That's it.
Chicken breast.
And then
we're gonna season it
with our salt
and our house seasoning.
And how long
is that gonna boil?
30 minutes to 45 minutes.
Okay. So, then
we're gonna shred it.
Okay.
Now, what's our next dish?
We're making
our homemade hot sauce.
And what do we call this?
Aji.
Okay. First of all,
we're gonna put
the jalapeños
into the pan.
And this is our secret
weapon -- tomate de árbol.
Tomatoes of the tree.
Tree tomato.
Well, it's actually
just a fruit.
It's like an unripe papaya.
This gets shipped in
from Ecuador?
Shipped in from Ecuador,
as well.
All right. So, we're
gonna drop that in.
We're gonna boil
for 15 to 20 minutes.
And then puree it?
Now we assembled
our homemade hot sauce.
We got red onion,
peas and carrots,
salt, fresh lime juice,
cilantro.
Very nice.
I love cilantro.
We pour that in,
and that's the salsa?
Aji.
Don't get me wrong.
It's --
Whoa! That's hot!
Can you taste
the jalapeño?
No! No, no, no, no.
[ Laughs ]
Aji for me.
Aji for you.
Okay.
This is gonna be
our mejunje dish.
Mejunje dish.
All right. Go.
Achiote oil and red onion.
Green bell peppers.
Salt, our house seasoning.
So, sweat down the peppers
and the onion.
Yep.
Peas and carrots.
Chicken.
And the cilantro.
Cilantro.
How long will this cook
together?
15, 20 minutes.
Then once it's done, it gets
mixed with the yellow rice?
Yes.
Oh.
Now we do that.
This is to make it pretty.
It's beautiful.
Sweet, ripe plantains.
We serve this with aji.
Here you go.
This is like
Ecuadorian fried rice.
The green bell pepper -- That's
probably my favorite part,
because that's
such a distinct flavor.
But the real surprise in it
are the peas and carrots.
Little pop.
Little velvety texture.
I mean, what's not to love
about that?
And that aji,
that salsa right there --
I'm stealing that one
for sure.
WOMAN: The meat
is definitely very savory,
but, then,
you have the sweet plantains.
Kind of like having a dessert
with your meal.
I can consider this
the closest to my home food.
I mean, just really authentic
Ecuadorian scratch-made, man.
Great stuff.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Whoa!
Huh?
See that?
Nice.
I'm out.
"Triple D's" over.
Good night.
[ Laughs ]
That was
not gonna be pretty.