Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Mmm!
...the bird is the word...
Got to love it.
...'cause we're chowing down
on all kinds of chicken.
Put it together, 'cause I'm
gonna drown in my own saliva.
In Des Moines, Iowa...
Shake the the left,
shake to the right.
...down-home
Southern cooking...
You're gonna scrape me
off the ceiling with a spatula.
...just like Grandma
used to make.
Yes!
[ Laughs ]
In Eugene, Oregon...
We're ready to eat, Guy.
Dig it.
...a smokin'
barbecue spot...
Gonna get busy
on that right there.
...serving up
some serious soul.
Step one of this adventure
is awesome.
And in Baltimore, Maryland...
Let's see the magic.
...a decades-old dive bar...
Now comes something
that I'm very fearful of.
...dishing out wings
with zing.
Those right there --
rather hot.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here on the east side
of Des Moines, Iowa,
in an area known
for great Mexican food.
And you're saying,
"Wait a second.
Des Moines, Iowa --
great Mexican food?"
Well, you know from "Triple D,"
no matter where we go,
we find great food.
So it's no surprise to me
that we're here to check out
a...Southern joint.
This is Patton's Restaurant
and Catering.
Gumbo and collard greens.
Pam's soul food is like
my grandmother's cooking.
Fried-fish po'boy
and French fries.
GIRL: Whenever I come into
Patton's, it always feels like
I'm in the middle of Louisiana,
even though I'm in Iowa.
FIERI:
That's because chef and owner
Pam Patton grew up in the South
before opening
this Midwestern spot in 2011.
So, great food is...
Southern food.
It's not too fancy,
and it's not too casual.
We've got fried chicken,
red beans and rice.
What makes
great fried chicken?
MAN:
Not too heavy, juicy.
Batter shouldn't be
the main part of it.
It should be the chicken.
What are we gonna make?
We're going to make
Southern fried chicken.
What are we gonna
serve this with?
Red beans and rice.
Got it.
So, we have
our raw chicken here.
We're going to brine it,
first of all, in this container.
I'm going to put
a little salt in...
Water...
and buttermilk.
There we go.
Okay.
So, now we get this
all mixed together.
We put it in the refrigerator
overnight.
Got it.
Now what are doing?
This is the very beginning
of the red beans and rice.
Excellent.
Can't have red beans and rice
without andouille sausage...
so we're frying up
our andouille.
While that's frying,
I'm gonna shred the turkey.
So, we're doing smoked turkey
wings just for the red beans.
Absolutely.
I like the way you roll.
Now, the beans are just
red beans soaked in water?
We boiled them
for about 90 minutes.
How am I looking
on the sausage?
I think we're ready
to go down.
Fantastic. Here we go.
Oh, look at that.
All that flavor going in.
All right.
Now I'm going to add my celery.
Celery.
Bell pepper, onion.
A mirepoix. I dig it.
Okay, veg is ready.
It goes down?
It's ready to go down.
All right.
Now you want to start
dropping turkey?
Absolutely.
There you go.
All that great flavor.
Oh, I'm telling you.
Now we got to season our beans
just a little bit, Guy.
Okay.
We're gonna put a little salt,
and a lot of Slap Ya Mama.
Bay leaves,
some Tabasco.
I like it.
Gumbo filé.
Okay.
Little Cayenne.
Little Creole seasoning.
And...
Cajun seasoning.
Got it.
Just a little garlic.
Mix it all together.
90 minutes covered.
Right.
That's a lot of work,
and I'm starving.
I got you.
Thank you.
Okay,
chicken's been brined.
I'm going to put the chicken
in the seasoned flour.
And then you shake it?
Absolutely.
You got to shake
to the left...
Uh-huh.
...shake to the right.
Shake to the left,
shake to the right.
Now we go to the fryer.
375,
about 7 to 8 minutes.
Whoa, hot and fast.
I know.
Okay, chicken's out.
Get a chance to cool down
for a second.
Red beans and rice
are finished.
Put it together, 'cause I'm
gonna drown in my own saliva.
All right,
we ready to go?
Look at that, though.
[ Laughing ]
Yes!
That was okay.
Oh.
Mmm! That's outrageous level
of red beans and rice.
Okay, good.
Thank you.
The smoked turkey leg
is really the key factor.
I get smoky, I get meaty,
I get super-tender beans.
I get it all together,
and with the fried chicken.
Mmm.
The chicken is very simple.
Nice breading.
Not greasy.
Old school. Delicious.
Thank you.
You rocked the house.
Fried chicken,
red beans and rice.
Enjoy.
MAN: Thank you.
The chicken is crispy
on the outside,
and it is very, very moist
on the inside.
Mmm. And it just kind of
melts in your mouth.
MAN:
Smoked turkey is not something
that overpowers the beans
or the andouille sausage,
but is a nice complement.
It's just cooked to perfection,
like everything that Pam does.
I have a gumbo coming up.
Now, were did you
learn to cook?
I had a great grandmother,
Gussie Hayes, who --
Time out.
Okay.
Gussie Hayes.
That's a name!
She taught me how to cook
when I was about 9 years old.
I just fell in love with it.
FIERI: And these days,
she still loves cooking up
both the savory and sweet side
of Southern.
Red-velvet waffle,
cream-cheese topping.
The red-velvet waffles
are delicious.
They melt in your mouth.
I don't know how else to
describe them.
I think
I called them heavenly.
Okay, what are we
making next?
We're gonna make
our red-velvet waffles.
You know, red velvet
is a big Southern staple.
We have
apple cider vinegar.
All of that, huh?
All of that.
Got some buttermilk.
Okay.
Some vanilla extract.
Got our eggs.
Our red food coloring.
Let's see
how red this is.
We're gonna whisk this.
Okay. That's red.
Okay, so, now...
Cocoa, baking soda,
salt, sugar.
Okay.
We've got
some cake flour here.
Cake flour?
That's right.
All right.
Let it go.
All right, so, now the dry
ingredients are together.
And we're going to pour our wet
ingredient in and mix that up.
The batter is done.
Now...
Gonna make that waffle
for you.
All right, Guy,
we're ready to go.
Pulling the waffle off.
Whoa, that's red.
Plate just like this.
You put the butter on,
and the cream-cheese topping
goes right on top.
That over a hot waffle...
You're gonna scrape me
off the ceiling with a spatula.
Pecans on top.
Okay.
Here we go.
Mmm.
That's a waffle-lover's
waffle.
It's got a little bit of crunch
to the outside.
Very soft.
Not overly sweet.
The cream-cheese
frosting/syrup/filling/nougat...
is great.
There is one person would walk
over hot coals for that --
my son Ryder.
Thank you so much.
Nice job.
Red-velvet waffles.
These are so delicious
that you can have them
for breakfast,
for dinner, for anything.
MAN:
The cream-cheese syrup on top
does just the right amount
of sweet.
"Cream-cheese syrup."
That's the best way
to put it.
That says "gym membership"
to me.
Southern-fried
chicken piccata.
Here's what I love
about what you do --
Everything is tied to you,
everything is tied to family,
and it feels like
you're at some family's home.
Thank you, Guy.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Gussie Hayes.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Baltimore, Maryland...
Wow, look at you.
...a neighborhood
watering hole...
Rub-a-dub-dub?
...showing off
its righteous menu makeover.
Call it a wrap. Call it
whatever you want. It's good.
I'm here in north Baltimore,
Maryland,
in an area known as Govans,
about two miles away
from Loyola University.
I'm here to check out a joint
that's got a lot of theories
on how they got their name.
Some folks say,
well, it was an swimming hole.
Others say
it was a spring that dried up.
Regardless
of how they got their name,
it's a name you'll never forget
on "Triple D."
This is Swallow at the Hollow.
MAN: Sliders up.
Swallow at the Hollow is more
than just a burger place.
Two minutes
on those wings.
There's always
something different.
Blackened-tuna pita.
I've been coming to the Swallow
since college.
I can remember when they had
greasy, grimy floors,
before it was purchased
by Aaron.
FIERI: That'd be chef and owner
Aaron Reinhart,
who's been serving up
scratch-made pub grub
since he took over in 2011.
You buy it,
and you re-invigorate the menu.
When I got here,
it was all frozen food.
Wow.
MAN: It's just a notch above
anything you're gonna find
at another dive bar.
MAN #2: Honey-ghost wings up.
MAN #3: I've probably had
the honey-ghost wings
50, 60 times easily.
I don't even order wings
anywhere else. Just here.
Now comes something
that I'm very fearful of.
Ghost pepper-honey wings?
Honey-ghost.
Those right there --
rather hot.
You're a scary man.
All right, first up?
Honey-ghost pepper
wing sauce.
Okay. Hit it, man.
Olive oil.
Onions in.
Diced serrano peppers.
And the fabulous
ghost peppers.
I don't even want
to look into it,
'cause the ghost peppers
are gonna eat my soul.
This'll sweat for a half-hour.
All right,
one full pot of coffee.
Hang on a second.
I'm gonna spot you.
[ Muffled ]
One -- One full pot of coffee.
Go get 'em.
Let that reduce.
This is a funky brew, dude.
I'm telling you right now.
While the coffee's reducing,
we're gonna make the slurry.
First step?
Start with the honey, honey.
Ketchup.
Worcestershire sauce.
Balsamic vinegar.
Orange juice.
Dark molasses.
Sugar.
Cayenne pepper.
Hot Mexican chili powder.
Garlic powder.
Dried thyme.
Dried basil.
Dried oregano.
Black pepper.
Kosher salt.
Okay, whisk that up.
Now, that will get incorporated
into the sweated onions,
peppers?
Yep.
Now you're gonna hit that
with an immersion blender?
I am.
Now we're gonna hit
the super slurry?
Ohh.
This is funky town.
[ Coughs ]
[ Laughs ]
I'm having flashbacks
from Smalley's.
[ All groaning ]
Oh, God.
It hurts all the way through.
Ohh.
Get the milk on hand.
Wings are done?
Wings are done.
Roll.
Honey-ghost pepper
wing sauce.
Okay.
What's in that blue-cheese
dressing?
Blue cheese,
buttermilk, sour cream.
I think you'll be
pleasantly surprised.
They're gonna be hot.
The wings are cooked perfectly.
They're very juicy.
There's the right amount
of heat -- just a little burn.
Now, don't get scared
by the ghost pepper.
It lets you know it's there,
kind of like a ghost.
And the sauce
is incredibly flavorful --
the Worcestershire
and the molasses.
The coffee, really, I think,
is probably the big kicker.
Outrageous. You could be known
for the wing alone just on this.
It's that good.
Cool.
That's what we're looking for.
I love the honey-ghost wings.
MAN: They're very nice
and crispy on the outside.
They're juicy on the inside.
And the end, it just has
the best kick to it.
Kind of the ghost heat.
Ghost heat.
MAN #2: The Swallow
at the Hollow's been iconic
here in the North Baltimore
neighborhood
for years and years.
How old is this joint?
This was here in the '40s.
My grandmother used to come here
on her lunch hour.
It was a dive, dive bar.
Aaron's cleaned it up but not
taken any of the character away.
It's still the Swallow, but it's
a place you bring the kids to.
The decor, the atmosphere,
the food, is amazing.
Steak going on the flat top.
Today, I'm having
the Swallow's beefsteak wrap.
Steak's perfectly cooked
medium-rare.
It's just dynamite.
What are we making?
Beefsteak wrap.
Let's see the magic,
the voodoo you do.
First thing,
we're gonna pound them out.
And then we make the marinade?
Then we make the marinade.
Got it.
Scallions.
Cilantro.
Red bell pepper.
Lime juice.
Garlic.
Sun-dried tomato.
Olive oil.
Looks good. Smells good.
Okay.
Rub-a-dub-dub?
Yep.
Now, how long's this meat
gonna marinate?
Anywhere from half an hour
to an hour.
All right,
let's cook the flank.
And a buttered tortilla.
After we rest the steak,
we're ready to slice it.
So, against the grain
on a bias? Excellent.
Start with the avocado.
Lettuce -- just enough
for a little bit of crunch.
Pico.
Now goes your steak.
Little bit of cheese.
Back on the grill to seal.
Once it's sealed,
it's ready to be cut and plated.
Wow, look at you,
plating genius.
Height, baby.
Height.
This is what we call, in the
rest of the country, a burrito.
[ Laughs ]
It isn't a "wrap."
I'm at home.
Great pico, tender meat,
avocado.
That's a good burrito.
Thank you very much.
I mean, really.
Call it a wrap.
Call it whatever you want.
Call it
a Mexican egg roll.
It's a burrito.
It's good.
Very tender, juicy.
Just a really good combination
that you wouldn't expect.
I love the Swallow.
It's like my second home.
You take a lot of pride
and respect
in doing this food right
and making it from scratch
at a local landmark that people
have known for years.
Nice job, Aaron.
Thanks a lot.
FIERI:
Up next in Eugene, Oregon...
[ Whistles ]
...a jammin'
soul-food joint...
...carrying on
a bigger-than-life legacy.
It's legit.
And I can't say that
about every barbecue place.
I'm here in Eugene, Oregon,
in one of the oldest
neighborhoods,
known as Whiteaker. Now,
I got a great story for you.
It starts off with this guy
that's got a band,
and it's called
Papa's Soul Kitchen.
Well, then he gets himself
a food cart,
and eventually,
he opens his own restaurant.
And you know
what the name's got to be.
That's right. This is
Papa's Soul Food Kitchen & BBQ.
MAN: Barbecued pork ribs,
baked beans, mac and cheese.
It's like you're transported
to New Orleans
without buying a plane ticket.
I actually used to be
a vegetarian,
so these are, like,
the kind of dishes
that make you happy
to no longer be a vegetarian.
MAN: Pulled-pork sandwich
and collard greens.
It's the best stuff happening
this side of the Mississippi.
FIERI:
Which has always been the dream
for Papa and his wife, Deb --
to dish out Southern grub
juke-joint style
to folks in the Northwest.
You and Big Papa
started this joint how long ago?
In 2002.
Unfortunately,
Papa passes.
Yeah.
And you kept it going.
He's not here, but people
can still remember him
every time they come
and eat here.
And the guy carrying on
Papa's legacy since 2009
is Chef Cliff Davis.
But everybody calls him Redbone.
I had some family history
with soul food,
so he met me and started
training me to be his sous-chef.
His protégé.
Yeah.
I love this place.
The people are generous.
The portion sizes
are generous.
I know I'm gonna get messy,
so I bib up.
I suit up.
I'm ready to go.
Barbecued-chicken plate with
collard greens and baked beans.
I'm doing the barbecued chicken.
Always comes off the bone
really easy.
Perfectly cooked every time.
MAN: It's got a good,
nice smoke ring,
and the barbecue sauce with the
rub is the ultimate combination.
What are we making first?
We're gonna bust out some
barbecue sauce, my man.
Dig it.
What I'm gonna do is start
with some tomato paste.
We got some ketchup here.
Brown sugar.
Our Worcestershire sauce.
This is Papa's recipe?
It is.
Molasses.
Got our honey.
Syrup.
Like, maple?
We use table syrup.
[ Chuckling ]
Got to love it.
Some liquid smoke.
Salt.
Fresh-ground black pepper.
Paprika.
[ Whistles ]
Chili powder.
Onion powder.
Mustard powder.
Cayenne pepper,
and a little bit of cinnamon.
Then we've got
the boat motor.
Once things are mixed up, we're
gonna add the vinegar slowly.
[ Whistles ]
We got one sauce
for all of our meats.
Step one of this adventure
is awesome.
Well, that's what
I'm talking about.
What are we making next?
We're gonna barbecue
some chicken, my man.
So, this chicken's been brining
for three days.
So, we gonna bust out
this dry rub.
Start off
with some brown sugar,
add our kosher salt
and black pepper.
White pepper.
Cayenne pepper.
Onion powder.
I'm just gonna preface
everything here
and just say we're using
everything that we have.
Garlic powder.
Chili powder.
Paprika.
We got rosemary.
Thyme.
Sage.
Oregano.
Basil.
BOTH: And marjoram.
That's it.
Okay.
So, I mix this all up
by hand.
I like to take the spoon
and just give them a good,
generous amount of dry rub.
Just take that right there
like that.
How long we let these smoke?
Seems to take
between three and four hours.
What temperature
you running that smoker at?
250.
We're ready to eat, Guy.
Dig it.
We serve this
with barbecue sauce.
Get a little
baked beans here.
And hit it
with a little collard green.
Mmm.
That chicken
is tender, juicy.
That brine gives it
a lot of love.
Mmm.
Mm-hmm.
Love dried beans.
Little sweet, little salt.
Great texture.
Mmm.
The greens are outrageous.
I mean...
You feel good
after eating them greens.
Mmm.
I'm a green machine.
It's legit.
And I can't say that
about every barbecue place.
That's real-deal.
Right on, man.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
Barbecue-chicken plate.
I would go swimming in
the barbecue sauce...head-first.
Barbecue's not something
you really find a lot in Oregon.
Mnh-mnh.
How does this rate?
It's definitely the best.
Barbecue pork ribs,
mac and cheese. Order up.
There's nothing like this
that can beat Papa Soul's.
Barbecue-chicken sandwich.
Papa was bigger than life.
So, he's a musician, and a great
one, from what I hear.
He was incredible.
He played the washboard.
He played the bass.
He was a percussionist.
He is alive and well
in here.
Yep.
This is a party.
Yeah.
FIERI:
And speaking of parties,
how about
this Southern celebration?
MAN:
One soul burger.
It's very soulful.
Tremendous flavor.
FIERI: And we're gonna get after
that when we come back.
Nothing stops
Soul Kitchen barbecue.
FIERI: In Eugene, Oregon,
Papa's Soul Food Kitchen & BBQ
is doing something
pretty unique in these parts --
dishing out
straight-up Southern staples.
Jambalaya and a gumbo.
You feel like you're in the
South when you come in here.
We're also gonna need
a catfish plate.
FIERI:
And Chef Redbone's carrying
the torch passed on from Papa,
the late owner
who started the joint.
What is great soul food?
You got to have some passion
for the recipes.
You got to have family history
for the food.
Catfish, yams,
red beans and rice. Order up.
I only have to eat once a day
if I come in here.
Soul burger!
Order up!
I'm having the soul burger. It
is a really good, spicy burger
with a little coleslaw and some,
like, frizzled onions on it.
MAN: You've got
this nice hunk of meat
that is sandwiched
between some great bread.
All right. So, the ground pork
from the pork butt?
Yep.
And this is gonna be
the beginning of the soul patty.
Sho' is.
Sho' is!
So, we're gonna take
this ground pork.
We're gonna mix together
the holy trinity --
onions, bell peppers,
and celery.
Kosher salt.
Got it.
Fresh-ground black pepper.
Some garlic powder.
Paprika.
Crystal Hot Sauce.
Some Worcestershire sauce.
The barbecue sauce.
That is killer
barbecue sauce.
We're gonna
mix this all up.
And we're gonna
portion out the patties?
We're going for 1/2 pound.
[ Whistles ]
How are we gonna
cook this?
We're gonna smoke these.
What happens when it rains?
Rain don't stop us
in Oregon.
Nothing stops
Soul Kitchen barbecue.
Okay,
let's go to the smoker.
Probably at
about 225 degrees.
We're gonna smoke them for about
an hour to an hour and a half.
So, we've got some
freshly-shredded cabbage here,
and the soul dressing --
mayonnaise, apple cider vinegar,
celery seed, and sugar.
Soul slaw down?
Soul slaw down.
We're gonna add
our smoked pork patty.
On the smoked patty,
we'll get our Papa Soul Kitchen
barbecue sauce.
We top it with
our Southern-fried onions.
Hit it with some fries,
top it with our cornmeal bun.
There you go, Guy.
All right. Let's get after this.
I'm going in.
Mmm.
The balance is fantastic.
Oh, thank you.
Not over-smoked
on the burger.
The slaw has the crunch.
The barbecue sauce
is spicy and sweet.
And then, those little, fried,
crunchy onions on top of it
just play it all together.
Mmm.
I'd get busy
on that right there.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Got your soul burger here.
MAN:
The flavors -- When you bite,
you have like five or six
different tastes.
It's making me full,
but doesn't mean I'm gonna stop.
Isn't just a restaurant. It's
more of, like, an atmosphere
and an experience
more than anything.
You know,
the way that Papa built this
and the way that you're carrying
through the tradition...
Mm-hmm?
Very impressive, bro.
Papa's very proud, man.
Appreciate it, Guy.
Excellent job.
[ Scatting ]
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Okay, so we're working
on that burger. Good.
Let's just got to camera one,
camera two, camera three,
camera four, camera five,
camera six!
[ Laughter ]