I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Bloo, bloo!
...we're cranking up
the comfort...
The best of the best.
...at righteous joints
serving serious soup.
That is
Soup Nation, man.
Perfect.
In Baltimore, Maryland...
There's someone trying to
get your attention over there.
Who?
...a pub
that's all-out Irish...
Out of bounds.
...except on the menu.
And gumbo is a big thing
in most Irish pubs.
Yes.
In Eugene, Oregon...
[ Electricity crackles ]
Oh, did you see the spark?
...a college town champ...
Are you a dipper?
Oh, yeah.
Chugger, dipper, swimmer.
[ Laughs ]
...where the bowl
is the boss.
That is a ridiculous
amount of soup.
And in Cincinnati, Ohio...
Drop it like it's...
Hot.
...phenomenal Vietnamese.
All kinds of flavor.
Going literally whole-hog.
Take all the leftover parts
of the pig that you have...
Yeah.
...cook them down.
Exactly.
Magic.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here in an old, familiar
neighborhood at "Triple D."
That's right.
Fell's Point
in Baltimore, Maryland.
Some of the greats are here --
BOP -- Brick Oven Pizza --
We got Blue Moon, and right
around the corner, Sip & Bite.
Now I'm here to check out
a funky Irish joint.
Wait till you see the menu.
This is Sláinte.
Pimento BLT, table three.
It's good food, good beer,
good people.
Fantastic Irish pub.
It's as close you can get
without actually being
in Ireland.
FIERI: Well, not quite.
When Patrick Russell
opened it in 2004,
he decided the grub
didn't have to match the pub.
The menu
is about as far away
from what I would call
traditional Irish.
We wanted to do
something different.
So, they brought in
Chris Marquis,
who has some serious cred
and some major ink.
"Neckbone."
That's your nickname?
Yep.
The chef is one of the top chefs
in the area.
Sliders in the window.
Food is absolutely delicious
no matter what you get.
Seafood gumbo is amazing.
This is the best gumbo.
The best of the best.
And gumbo is a big thing
in most Irish pubs.
Yes. Irish gumbo.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
Fire it up.
Little oil, garlic.
Onions.
Bunch of celery.
Green bell.
A little red bell,
andouille.
So, cook that down,
sweat it all down.
Then we're gonna take
our dark roux
then we start adding
spices.
Kosher salt, little oregano,
cayenne, garlic powder.
There we go.
That's what we're looking for.
Onion powder, a little pepper,
paprika, gumbo filé.
Sassafras.
If it's not in there,
it doesn't count.
Bay leaves.
Little thyme.
A little thyme.
Then Worcestershire.
It's a
good-looking gumbo.
Vegetable juice.
That I haven't seen
in gumbo before.
Could be our secret.
Then we're gonna add
white seafood stock.
We're gonna let this continue
to cook and reduce...
For about an hour.
Throw all the seafood in.
Peeled and
de-veined shrimp.
Crayfish tails.
Blue crab. Got it.
Blue crab. Definitely.
Little rice.
Some green onions.
That's dynamite.
You really have
the bounty of the county
with all the great seafood
you got.
It's rich, it's deep,
it's flavorful.
But the key is the heat.
Can you see it?
There's a little bit
of sweat coming through.
Starting
to warm up a bit.
And right now,
if we just took a minute
and did a little
"Wayne's World"
and gave a little
"bloo, bloo."
We could be
in New Orleans.
It's legit.
Nice job, Neckbone.
Thank you, boss.
Just the right consistency,
just the right spice.
WOMAN: Seafood gumbo.
MAN: It's got just enough heat
to make you know
that it's there,
allow you to enjoy it
without burning your tongue off.
Food's splendid. It's an
experience more than anything.
FIERI: That's because
the ambience here
comes straight from
the Emerald Isle.
I'm in Ireland,
bought all the furniture.
But I don't have a name
for the restaurant.
So I said,
"Okay, sláinte."
That means
"cheers to your health."
I'm like, "I like it."
Is this
a typical Irish pub?
The food's very unique.
This is not what you find
in an Irish pub.
Irish Bibimbap
in the window.
Kind of a Korean dish, but they
add the local corned beef to it
with a little bit
of an Irish flair to it.
We're corning some brisket
for our Irish Bibimbap.
All right,
so we're gonna take our brisket,
then we're gonna take
some hot water,
and we're gonna mix up
some brown sugar,
some kosher salt,
some garlic cloves,
cinnamon stick,
and black peppercorns --
I like to add a lot --
clove.
I do ground mustard,
some bay leaves,
cure salt -- pink salt.
Stir this up real good.
We're gonna
just pour that.
How long are we gonna
let this brine?
Five to seven days.
A lot of people boil it.
We actually braise ours.
Braise in equal parts water
and vinegar.
Goes in the oven at 450
for 4 hours.
Gonna pull it
out of the oven.
Okay,
corned beef's done.
MARQUIS:
All the way up.
Take our corned beef.
Look at that.
With a joint like this,
I expect the corned beef
to be righteous.
All right,
chop it up real rustic.
There's someone trying to
get your attention over there.
Who?
Nice.
All right, so we're gonna
take that.
[ Muffled ]
Wait a second.
Dude.
Oh!
The braising it
in vinegar
puts it in
a whole 'nother level.
I mean, that is
super-righteous corned beef.
We got to make
some Irish Bibimbap.
We need some screeching-hot pans
for this dish, though.
A little bit
of this rice.
We want to get a char
on this rice.
All right.
Corned beef.
We'll start adding veggies.
Little green pepper,
red onion.
Yeah, you want,
like, a nice sauté.
So, we're gonna take
our crisped rice,
our little veggie corned-beef
stir fry.
FIERI: Crazy.
Take our pickled cabbage.
Nice, little dollop.
What a dish.
An egg.
A little bit of Sriracha.
Attaboy.
Sesame, micro celery,
and some green onion.
Dude,
this is out of bounds.
You got
all kinds of things.
You got a play
on sauerkraut going here
with the pickled cabbage.
You got the rice
coming in.
Look at the colors
from the egg
to the variety of fresh veggies
to the corned beef,
which is out of bounds.
Thank you.
I love it.
That's a dynamite dish.
MAN: Combination of sriracha
and corned beef
is not something you'd expect
to work, but it's fantastic.
WOMAN #2: It's my favorite dish
on the menu.
It's what I come back for
every time.
It's a real nice place
to hang out with your friends.
Sláinte.
Nice job.
What a fun joint.
Thank you, man. I appreciate it.
That's great.
FIERI:
Coming up, in Eugene, Oregon...
Dude, come on.
...we're taking
a worldwide journey...
That's straight
out of Compton --
Or, I'm sorry --
straight out of Cairo.
...at one soup-centric spot.
That's Flavor City, which
is right next to Flavortown.
It's a much bigger
population.
I'm here on High Street
in the Market District of
Eugene, Oregon,
about a mile and a half
from the university.
Now, I am here
to check out a joint
where a dude made
his restaurant dream come true.
He started off with a cart,
selling soup
over at the university.
15 years later,
he's got his own restaurant,
and he's serving up exactly
what everybody in the cold
Pacific Northwest wants.
That's right -- soup.
This is Soup Nation.
STERN: Jamaican
red beans and rice.
We crave it.
The soups here are fantastic.
Hungarian
mushroom and potato up.
It can get
fairly cool and rainy here.
There's nothing
that kind of hits at the bone
better than soup.
Roger that.
Well, he puts some passion
into his food.
I really wanted
to embrace world flavors,
not be bound by
any one type of cuisine.
Figured soup was
a good vehicle.
It is the common denominator.
It can go anywhere.
FIERI: So, Mark Stern
opened a cart in '97
then set up shop here
in 2011.
There's always something
slightly different.
I got
the Bangkok sweet potato.
And with the bread,
it's really comforting.
It's a scratch recipe,
and it's so good,
and it holds up
to dipping it in the soup,
which is the whole point
of having bread with soup.
Whole-wheat sourdough.
Is going for what soup?
It's basically going with
all of our soups.
Okay.
So let's get into this.
Low-gluten flour.
Then we have
our whole-wheat flour.
Next we're gonna put our
sugar in, salt, instant yeast.
Okay.
And we'll mix it up.
This is nice.
Columbus traded this in,
didn't he?
I believe so.
[ Electricity crackles ]
Oh, did you see the spark?
I always see the spark.
[ Laughs ]
"Local chef
kills celebrity chef."
Yeah, "news at 5:00."
Yeah.
110-degree water.
And the sourdough starter
and unsulfured molasses.
A local baker here
helped me formulate this.
[ MACHINE WHIRRING ]
Sorry.
Not that time, huh?
How long's this gonna go?
About 10 minutes,
15 minutes.
Then we bring it out,
form it in a loaf.
So, we oil it up.
Okay,
let it proof overnight.
Cut it and score it.
Right.
Deflates.
And bake it off.
what temp?
350 in the oven,
30 minutes.
[ Sniffs ] Mmm.
Are you a crust guy?
Most definitely.
That's soup bread
right there.
Great for dipping.
Are you a dipper?
Oh, yeah.
Chugger, dipper, swimmer.
[ Laughs ]
The bread -- Oh, it's delicious.
Slightly sweet. It complements
the soup perfectly.
What's the first soup
we're gonna make?
We're gonna make
"The Fire in Cairo."
Got it.
I have a "Fire in Cairo."
It's filled with lamb
and chickpeas,
and it's a fantastic soup.
You don't see
enough lamb soup.
We actually get local, organic,
sustainably raised lamb.
All right,
let's do this.
So, first we're gonna sauté
the ground lamb in olive oil.
All right, so the lamb's out,
cooled down, drained off.
Next step?
More olive oil.
Yellow onion, salt, diced
red bells, diced green bells.
Let that sweat.
Minced serrano.
Nice.
Minced garlic, coriander,
sumac -- nice and lemony,
nice and earthy.
Smells great.
Then we add our stock.
This is chicken.
You make your own stocks?
We do from scratch.
Bring that to a simmer.
Cook garbanzos.
Ground lamb that we
already cooked goes back in now.
Lemon juice.
Is this harissa?
Exactly.
A little harissa.
A little bit of spice.
So, let that simmer.
When it's done,
just serve it
with that sourdough bread
that I ate a loaf of.
You got it.
Minced parsley.
Please. All right.
It's outrageous.
From the unique flavor
of the lamb, the garlic,
the little bit of the heat,
the little bit of the acid.
The sumac and harissa
are what do it
combined together with
that delicious chicken stock.
Mmm.
It is like a Greek pozole.
It's got a lot
of those elements.
That sourdough is outrageous,
and it soaks it up really nice.
That's straight out
of Compton, man.
That is phenomenal.
Or, I'm sorry --
straight out of Cairo.
Very tasty soup.
Had a little kick to it.
It was fantastic.
What are we
gonna make next?
We're gonna make
the Peruvian pork and quinoa.
Love pork and quinoa.
I do.
FIERI: Which means I'm sticking
around to get some of that
when we come back.
Mmm.
FIERI: Near the university
in Eugene, Oregon,
Mark Stern's soup empire started
from humble beginnings.
I went to the University of
Oregon, went to the soup cart.
It was my staple.
It really much
put me through school.
FIERI: Now there's
the brick and mortar,
serving up everything
from Southeast Asian...
STERN:
Bangkok sweet potato.
...to Eastern European...
Hungarian
mushroom and potato up.
...even south of the border --
way south.
Large
Peruvian pork and quinoa.
The pork and quinoa soup
is delicious.
The quinoa gives a nice,
little earthy background to it.
It's so flavorful.
So, what are we making?
The pork stock for
the Peruvian pork and quinoa.
Fresh pork bones,
carrots, celery.
Yellow onions.
Bay leaves.
Whole garlic cloves.
And a bunch
of peppercorns.
Roast this in the oven
how long?
375, 1 hour.
Take all that,
drop it in the stock pot,
and then start to make
the stock.
You got it.
Cover the bones and veg
in water.
Totally gonna cook down.
And then strained.
And the reason
we're calling it Peruvian?
It's the flavor profile.
It's got roasted yams,
it's got turmeric.
Okay.
And, of course, quinoa,
grain staple of Peru.
So, what are we making?
We're gonna make
our pork butt.
Shoulder staple
of the pig.
Yes. [ Laughs ]
Pork butt.
Salt and pepper's
all it's getting.
In the oven what temp?
We like this 250,
overnight.
[ Whistles ]
Pork's done.
We'll dice it up
and crank up the flame.
Olive oil.
Yellow onion's going in.
Sea salt,
diced carrots going in.
Minced garlic,
turmeric, coriander.
Let that cook down.
Next we got
the pork stock.
Look at that.
That's Flavor City, which
is right next to Flavortown.
It's a much bigger
population.
Pork butt.
Roasted yams.
Cooked quinoa.
Love that.
Crazy for quinoa.
And lemon juice.
Wow, look at that quinoa --
just soaked it all up.
Peruvian pork and quinoa
are ready.
Okay, hit it.
That is a ridiculous
amount of soap.
A little cilantro
for you, sir.
Okey-dokey.
Now you can definitely smell
the roasted pork.
Dude, come on.
The pork is roasted.
That's awesome.
Then you get a little sweetness
coming from the roasted yam.
I think the key to this is
the richness of that pork stock.
Just really adds
such depth to it.
It's creamy and rich without
having to be a cream-based soup.
Just really straightforward
and incredibly good.
Mmm.
Out of bounds.
That is Soup Nation, man.
Perfect name. Perfect.
It's absolutely delicious.
WOMAN:
Pork is really succulent.
It's like it's been stewed,
and the meat just falls apart
and melts in your mouth.
I like a little body
to my soup.
Right.
And this has got body.
Did this deliver?
Yeah, this delivered.
Very much so.
STERN:
Peruvian pork and quinoa.
A really great chef
makes really great soup.
And you've locked it down.
You've perfected your recipes.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
Way to go.
FIERI: Up next, a Vietnamese
spot in Cincinnati...
I dig it.
...cooking up
the killer pho...
Got to live life
on the edge.
Yes, you do.
...and a meat-and-cheese
sandwich spin.
I've eaten
a lot of bánh mi,
but I don't know
that I've ever seen head cheese.
So, I'm here
in Cincinnati, Ohio,
at the Findlay Outdoor Market.
Now, this is the oldest market
in the state of Ohio.
It opened in 1852, and it's been
running ever since.
Now, when you come here,
I mean, you're talking
awesome produce stands,
all kinds of shops,
and the food is off the hook.
And I hear a joint
you got to visit, no question,
for some bomb pho is right here
at Pho Lang Thang.
NGUYEN: Order up.
I've got a beef bánh mi
and a goi cuon
going out to table 24.
This is the best authentic
Vietnamese food
you can get in Cincinnati.
All of his recipes go back
two to three generations.
MAN #1: When you look at
the servers delivering the food,
you're like, "That looks
so good. I should try that."
FIERI: The dude who's creating
all that curiosity
is co-owner Duy Nguyen.
I'm actually American,
born here,
but my folks
are from the 'Nam.
After learning to cook
from his mom,
Duy and some buddies
scraped up enough cash
to open this joint in 2010.
Now he's dishing up 300 bowls
of authentic pho a day.
WOMAN: Beef pho.
The pho broth is fantastic.
It's always super-fatty,
rich, delicious.
It's comfort food for me,
and I just love it.
FIERI:
So, where we gonna start?
We're gonna start off
with the bones.
Okay. So, ox tail.
Ox tail,
got some femur bones.
Wow.
Next up,
we add our brisket to it.
So, we take our beef scraps,
toss it in there, as well.
Okay.
Kosher salt in there.
From here,
we add the water.
Now let it simmer.
Takes about three hours.
Gonna pull out
the brisket.
Like bobbing for brisket.
Now we're gonna
drop the tendon in.
Nothing says more yum
than tendon.
Let it sit in there
overnight.
How many hours
to get a finished product?
We start at about 1:00
right after our lunch rush,
and we finish it right before
our lunch rush, at 11:00.
So, every day,
you're playing leapfrog.
Got to live life
on the edge.
Yes, you do.
Next up?
Roasted onions...
roasted ginger, roasted spices,
and cinnamon, as well, too.
Sugar, kosher salt.
Rock sugar.
Rock sugar, rock candy.
Little bit
of mushroom seasoning.
And MSG.
And last
but not least...
Little sieve
just to push everything down.
Put the top back on,
come back three hours later,
ready to plate it.
Okay.
Fresh pho noodles.
It's just a rice noodle.
Yep.
About 30 seconds or so.
Got it.
Start placing the meat in.
First we go with brisket,
then we got our meatballs,
tripe, some tendon, and we got
our rare eye of the round.
Eye of the round.
Yep.
Little bit
of white onions,
green onions,
some cilantro, as well.
Got it.
And then ladle
the hot broth on.
Then we're gonna
finish off
with a little bit
of black pepper on top.
That's outstanding.
Mmm.
Tender noodles,
great meatball.
I think that there's
so many components to it.
The balance is great.
The flavors are subtle.
Delicious, man.
Great job, chef.
Thank you.
Slightly salty,
full of beef flavor.
The smell of the pho
wafts across the block.
You can't not come in here.
How long is a line to get into
this joint on a Saturday?
Uh, about
an hour and a half.
No!
Yeah.
FIERI: Maybe that's 'cause
the specialties here
you just can't find anywhere.
Got a pork bánh mi.
Let's go, guys.
MAN #2:
Bánh mi's one of my favorites.
The richness of that pâté
cut with a little bit
of the pickled veg,
down to the richness
of the head cheese.
I've eaten
a lot of bánh mi,
but I don't know
that I've ever seen head cheese.
This is, like, probably
the favorite in my family.
So, take all the leftover parts
of the pig that you have...
Yeah.
...cook them down,
throw them in a sandwich
with some vinegary vegetables.
Exactly.
Magic.
So, first start
with some pig face.
That's great.
We boil it off.
Take it out,
slice it into small pieces.
We're gonna
drop the pig face in.
Drop it like it's...
Hot.
Got pork neck,
some ham, as well.
Okay.
Black pepper, garlic,
pink salt, sugar.
So, cook this down
for how long?
30 minutes.
Releases all the collagen
and the juices and the fats?
Yep.
Then you'll put it
into a mold and let it cool?
Yep.
Mm.
It's all nice
and gelatinous here.
Just slice it
really thin.
Mmm.
I think
I'm having the knee.
Now we're ready
to build our sandwich.
All right, buddy.
Start off with
a 7-inch baguette, open it up,
and actually hollow out
a little bit of the core.
Garlic mayo.
House-made pâté.
Chicken liver?
Yep.
We're gonna go with
our head cheese next.
Barbecue pork.
All kinds of flavor.
And then the cha lua, which
is like a Vietnamese bologna.
Our pickled carrots
and daikon.
Got some cucumbers, jalapeños,
and cilantro to top it off.
Gorgeous sandwich, man.
Great bread.
I mean, there's just
so many different components.
The balance is great.
Thank you.
Mmm.
As you chew it, you just get --
"Oh, there it is."
Oh, now I got some sour,
now I got some heat,
now I got a little jalapeño,
now I got the freshness
of the cucumber.
It just keeps trumping itself
as you enjoy it.
Exactly.
I dig it.
Thank you.
The inside is so spongy.
It really absorbs
the flavor of the meat.
The pickled daikons and carrots
gives it a good crunch.
I've never had head cheese
before. I like it.
It's neat for people
to walk in here
and get a full
cultural experience.
Exactly.
Outstanding, man.
Really.
Thank you.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You guys still shooting?
I'm just full feeding
at this point.
I don't need
any more camera on me.
If you want to go somewhere,
dude, whatever.
All right, cool.
Skateboard or something.
[ Laughter ]