Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That is awesome!
...buried by bread...
Meaty Cheesy Goodness.
...or nestled in noodles?
All by hand, baby.
We're getting to the meat
in the middle.
Huh? Like that?
In Baltimore, Maryland...
This is the kind of place
that everybody wishes
they had in their town.
...a cozy Italian joint...
Old-school, real deal.
...where homemade pasta
is the priority.
You sure delivered, man.
That is awesome.
In Eugene, Oregon...
Thanks, camera.
...a funky food truck...
I like big butts.
And I cannot lie.
...stacking up
some serious sandwiches.
I want to call that one
"Meaty Cheesy Greatness."
And in Cable, Wisconsin...
A lot of heart and soul
in what this girl
delivers. Trust me.
...a small-town
scratch-made oasis...
Think about it!
[ Laughs ]
...from a chef
who clearly knows her audience.
[ Laughs ]
I'm not gonna make it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here in Cable, Wisconsin,
in Bayfield County.
And this county, they
don't even have one stoplight,
and this in the middle of the
Chequamegon National Forest,
about two hours
from Minneapolis,
about an hour and half away
from Duluth.
And in this town, you can count
all the restaurants on one hand,
but from what a lot of locals
tell me,
the joint you need to check out
is right at Brick House Café.
LUDZACK:
The panini caprese.
It's not typical
Northwoods dining.
Crème brûlée French toast.
Creative combinations,
inventive thinking.
Really doesn't matter
which meal you come here for.
You're gonna have
a really good meal.
FIERI:
All cranked out by self-trained
chef Heather Ludzack,
who had deep family roots
in Cable
while making a living
for herself in Seattle.
Just decided I needed to be
back here with my family.
So, she moved back
and turned an empty, old house
into this joint in '05.
What kind of food
do you do here at the...
♪ Brick House? ♪
We just sort of do whatever.
Bourbon bleu cheese burger.
WOMAN:
It's comfort food with elegance.
[ Bell dings ]
LUDZACK: Espresso-barbecue
pulled pork sandwich.
WOMAN: It's excellent. It's got
espresso in the barbecue.
So it's got kind of an earthy,
savory flavor to it.
Anything that you got
to eat with a fork
that's a sandwich is...
You know you're in.
Yeah.
What are we making first?
Espresso-barbecue
pulled-pork sandwich.
That looks like a pork butt
right now.
That is a pork butt.
We making a dry rub.
Start with kosher salt,
brown sugar, white sugar,
garlic powder, paprika,
pepper, ground mustard,
cumin, and ginger.
Rub it all up.
Why does she kind of give me
some Jack Black looks?
Think about it!
[ Laughs ]
You're only rocking
part-time!
That is awesome!
So, we take our pork butt,
cut slits in the top,
shove some whole garlic cloves
in there.
Then we take our rub...
Just throw it
on there, baby.
I cover it
with food-service film.
[ Chuckling ]
Food-service film.
You're not allowed out at night
by yourself.
Not so much.
Give me a little dance,
Jack.
Right?
[ Laughs ]
I'm not gonna make it.
We let it sit overnight.
We go to the oven --
425 for 20 minutes.
Now?
We are going to make
a marinade --
Worcestershire,
apple juice,
then brown sugar,
salt, pepper.
Whisk it up,
and we pour it over the top.
Wrap it back up?
Yep.
Back to the oven.
Back to oven.
At 250 for about 4 hours.
Now what are we making,
princess?
We're gonna make
our espresso-barbecue sauce.
Olive oil, onion,
minced garlic, ketchup.
Okay.
Okay?
Honey.
Put in some salt,
soy sauce, cider vinegar.
Very nice.
Freshly brewed espresso.
And then brown sugar.
Bring it to a boil first,
then let it simmer
for about four hours
till it gets nice and thick.
So, now we take
the cooled pork butt?
Yep. Shred it up.
And then where are we going
from here?
We go straight to the flat-top,
and we hit it
with a little bit
of our espresso-barbecue sauce.
That's that like glaze
on there.
Yep. Kind of caramelize,
a little bit of [babbles]
I don't know. That was
more "Wayne's World," right?
We've got it flipped.
Get it nice and juicy.
Right on there.
More of our
espresso-barbecue sauce.
We put a little of our
apple-cabbage slaw on here,
bun, french fries.
That's all she wrote.
Mmm.
Good texture in your pork --
not overcooked, not dried out.
Espresso-barbecue sauce
is what makes it.
The richness of the coffee
gives it a little smoky flavor.
Nice job.
Thank you.
It's got a taste that's
just different than
what you're expecting.
Can taste that hint of coffee.
It's a two-napkin sandwich.
I would have never expected
to have this kind of food
in a small town like Cable.
People come here
for a different experience.
You can come here and eat
this natural, good,
flavorful-tasting food.
So, here's the deal. We're
hanging out in Cable, Wisconsin,
with a really cool,
and funny, chef.
When we come back,
one more dish.
Some thing off the breakfast
menu. What do you say?
Sure. Let's do it.
See you in a bit.
So, "Triple D" hanging out here
in Cable, Wisconsin.
We are at the home
of the Brick...
♪ House ♪
Huh? Like that?
You told me
that breakfast is big here.
So we're tell me
what we're gonna make.
We're gonna make
crème brûlée French toast.
Definitely not your
traditional French toast.
French toast ecstasy.
It's delicious.
What are we making here?
What's this part?
This is our
caramelized pears.
We start with a little butter.
Then we add our slice pears.
Here we're gonna make
our caramel sauce.
Evaporated milk.
Evaporated milk? Okay.
White sugar, brown sugar,
dark corn syrup.
So, we let that get
a little gooey and caramel-y.
We let our pears
keep going here.
And then we're gonna hit it
with a little creme de cacao.
Great.
We let this reduce down.
These get a little caramel-y
and brown and --
Is that a TV show?
"Caramely and Brown"?
Two tough cops,
living on the streets.
[ Laughs ]
It's Caramely and Brown.
We're gonna make
our batter --
eggs,
French vanilla creamer.
So a little
hazelnut liqueur?
And cinnamon.
Whisk that up.
Then we're gonna make
our dredge --
crushed pecans and
crushed toasted hazelnuts.
This is gonna go
in the egg wash...
...and right
onto the flat-top.
Grill it about three minutes
a side
till it gets nice
and crispy and toasty.
Crispy, toasty,
and nutty.
Then we take
our caramelized pears
and the caramel --
that right over the top.
[ Whistles ]
Little whipped cream
that's just heavy whip, sugar,
a little vanilla,
And a little caramel.
A little pear,
a little nut.
That's fantastic.
If the sun wasn't out, I
would think I'm having dessert.
The nuts on it are the key,
and the way you ground them up,
'cause you really allow them
to work with the batter
and create this crust
on the outside of the bread.
But the saltiness
and the crunch
really is what carries
the whole thing.
You just do all these things
correct.
Awesome.
Thank you.
WOMAN: The caramel and pecans
and hazelnut
is a delightful addition.
Most French toasts are a little
eggy, and this is not eggy.
I'm stuffed, and I won't
even need to have lunch.
It's sort of
my lunch-brunch meal.
MAN: Usually, we'll look
around the office and say,
"Anyone feeling Brick House?",
and the answer's always, "Yes."
WOMAN: It's extraordinary, and
it's a little slice of heaven.
I tell all of my friends
when the come into town
that they have to go
to the The Brick House.
This the epicenter of great food
and friends and family,
and you're just like
the big sister of the
town, aren't you?
You're getting
all teary-eyed.
I am.
Well, it's nice to hear.
Thank you.
"H," you do
a really good job.
A lot of heart and soul
in what this girl
delivers. Trust me.
In every bite, it's like
eating at a family picnic.
FIERI: Coming up
in Baltimore, Maryland...
Buon appetito.
...a legit pasta bar...
May be some fireworks.
...serving up something
I just can't resist.
You have truffles and
don't know what to do
with them, send them to me.
So, I'm here
in Baltimore, Maryland,
about two miles from downtown
in the Hampden neighborhood.
Now, we're right in the center
of all the universities.
Now, I hear
that they've got a place
where you sit at the counter
as the chefs cook.
The dude that owns it is from
Italy, and the place is legit.
This is Grano Pasta Bar.
Penne alla vodka.
People come here for the pasta
because it is homemade.
We get to watch people cook
before our eyes.
There you go,
beautiful lady.
Once you find out it's
here, then it's hard
to go anywhere else.
FIERI: But blink,
and you might miss it.
At only 400 square feet,
this joint's been making room
for just one thing
since Naples-born chef
Gino Troia opened in '08.
This an Italian
pasta restaurant.
Pasta is the foundation,
no pizza.
WOMAN: The homemade pasta --
You can tell it's fresh,
it has just been made.
Is the pasta tender?
It's off the hook.
Linguine
vongole positano.
The clam dish is delicious.
It has a lovely, light sauce
with just a touch of wine.
What are
we gonna make first, chef?
Vongole positano
with the clams.
First, we're gonna make
the tagliolini.
And this is an extruder. So,
it's gonna make out the pasta.
So, some semolina.
You throw the egg in?
Yep.
Cut it right here.
Okay, so now we're gonna spread
it out even more.
Yes.
And then cut it
for the tagliolini.
That's correct.
Got it.
Okay, we got the pasta ready.
All right, next up?
Extra virgin olive oil,
some garlic.
These are baby clams.
You got to love Baltimore
and the seafood.
We'll add a little
chili pepper.
A little
red chilli flake.
Herbs de provence.
A little white wine.
White wine.
Cover them till they open.
A little salt.
May be some fireworks.
And next up?
Some of our heirloom tomatoes.
Now we have some spinach.
Now we drop the pasta?
Yes.
Couple of minutes.
So, we finish the pasta
just a little bit
right there in the pan?
Exactly.
Then the clams go in
on top.
Mmm. Delicious.
There's a lot of flavor,
simple ingredients.
Boy, I love the spinach
included in there.
The clams
aren't overcooked.
I think out of everything,
the tomatoes are what add
the diversity to the dish.
They're very important.
Coming from Naples, you're
gonna do a dish like this,
you better deliver,
and you sure delivered, man.
That is awesome.
Fantastic.
Just has the right amount
of herbs in the sauce.
Gino is very particular
about making sure
that he gets whatever is fresh
that day.
You guys
are from this area?
Yes.
Lots of Italian joints -- How
any of these kinds of places
you can sit here
and watch everybody cook?
Not a whole lot.
Everything
just comes together
in an atmosphere
that's buzzing.
TROIA: Ravioli ai funghi.
Ravioli with a cream sauce,
wild mushrooms,
and sprinkles of truffles
on top.
Now we're gonna make
the filling for the ravioli.
Yes.
Our first ingredient
is the cooked mushrooms.
Cremini
and the shiitakes?
Yes.
All right.
Goat cheese.
The ricotta.
Parmigiano reggiano.
All right.
Gonna put it together.
Pulse it.
Not too much?
No, no.
You want to have
some texture.
Exactly.
Beautiful.
Now I'm gonna fill them.
Great.
Okay.
I'm gonna put a little egg wash
so that they seal together.
All by hand, baby.
Get all the air out.
Get some of the air out.
I'm going to cook the ravioli
in boiling water.
Got it.
All right, next up?
A little butter.
Okay.
Caramelized onions.
Next, half-and-half.
Half-and-half? Okay.
A little Marsala.
Nothing loves mushrooms
more than Marsala.
So, we get the pasta till it's
about 3/4 of the way done,
then finish it
in the sauce?
Yes.
And then we shave some truffle
on top of it.
I have a massive
truffle addiction.
If you have truffles and
don't know what to do
with them, send them to me.
I'm gonna put a little truffle
on top of them.
It's okay.
Have a heavy hand.
Buon appetito.
It's rich.
It's light.
It's earthy.
That's outrageous.
I mean, you hand-make
everything --
pasta, the filling.
Delicious dish.
Thank you.
Outrageous.
It just almost melts
in your mouth.
MAN: When you taste it,
the mushrooms and the
natural flavors come through.
This is my Aunt Patty
and my Uncle Ray.
So, break it down.
I never had anything so good
in my life.
It's so delicious. It's really
tender, very flavorful.
A place like this, good food --
What more could you ask for?
It's the bomb.
See?
And you wondered where
I came up with all the lingo.
The best restaurant
in town.
Old-school, real deal.
This is the kind of place
that everybody wishes
they had in their town.
What a great job.
Thank you, Gino.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Up next in Eugene, Oregon...
[ Imitates chicken ]
Bawk! Bawk!
...a super-sandwich spot...
You can make anything
into a sandwich.
...that's aiming
to save the day.
You can be this big
and look like you're 21
if you come eat
at The Sandwich League.
So, I'm here to check out
a joint that's sandwiched
between a tattoo parlor
and well-known local brewery.
I'm in the Whiteaker
neighborhood of Eugene, Oregon.
Now, why am I here to check out
this masterful meat
in the middle?
I mean, what's at "steak"
for this new "Triple D" joint?
Well, from what a lot of people
tell me,
this is the coolest thing going
since sliced bread.
This is The Sandwich League.
Man, it's awesome.
Got a Pork-A-Licious
and Sloppy Fries.
Probably some of the best food
I've ever put in my mouth.
Dawn does it all in the kitchen.
FIERI: That's chef Dawn Sellars,
who cashed in her 401(k) in 2012
to build her own food truck
inspired
by her favorite superheroes.
So, Sandwich League
after "Justice League"?
Yes.
You can do so many things
with sandwiches.
You can make anything
into a sandwich.
Got a Shroominator.
She never sends out
anything less than perfect.
MAN: Local meats,
really good ingredients --
You can't get anything better.
Got a Pork on Pork.
Perfect barbecue-pork sandwich.
MAN:
And then it has bacon.
You add bacon to anything,
it's gonna make it better.
We're gonna make
a Pork on Pork sandwich.
Pork on Pork?
We're gonna get
our pork butt ready.
We're gonna start with
a little bit of salt, cumin.
Yeah, you use cumin
like you're from Mexico.
Smell it!
And with the pork,
I use coriander, also.
Paprika, chili powder,
good-old garlic powder --
'cause I love it --
apple-cider vinegar.
Throw this in here?
Yep.
Get that all nestled in there
real nice.
That's one whole butt.
It is.
I like big butts.
And I cannot lie.
[ Laughs ]
In the oven.
350, about 3½ hours.
We pull the pork
after it comes out,
and we separate
all the fat out.
And then we're gonna toast
your bun,
and we're gonna get
some of that delicious pork
right on the grill.
Some bacon.
You start with the pork,
and then we do more pork.
There you go. Look at that.
Look at the magic.
And then
we're gonna sauce it up.
We've got our barbecue sauce,
and we've got
our cheese sauce.
I like it.
We put french fries
on our sandwiches --
three, sometimes four, depending
on the size of the fries.
It just depends on
if you're wild.
Nice amount
of cilantro slaw,
topped off
with crispy fried onions.
There you go --
Pork on Pork.
[ Whistles ]
Thanks, camera.
[ Whistle! ]
Pork's really tender.
I love the slaw 'cause I like
the freshness of it.
You definitely have
a lot of pork.
And it's definitely
very rich.
It's a monster
of a sandwich.
Quality ingredients,
a lot of creativity.
You are full of ideas, girl.
I will give you that.
Nice job.
Thank you.
It's super-good,
really flavorful.
It's gestalt.
It's what?
The whole is greater
than the sum of the parts.
I'm gonna start using
that.
Maybe to describe
the 'hood I'm in.
Whiteaker neighborhood
is really spunky.
Primarily a lot of artists and
freethinkers live around here.
My partner and I own
the tattoo shop.
So we eat here daily,
as much as we can.
Meaty Cheesy.
I definitely go with Meaty
Cheesy Goodness every time.
MAN: Sometimes, grilled cheese
just isn't enough.
So you got to have
a little extra ooey, gooey,
and meaty in there.
So, what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
a Meaty Cheesy Goodness.
Meaty Cheesy Goodness.
We're gonna start
with a barbecue sauce.
This is mini sweet peppers,
serrano peppers,
some onion, garlic,
black pepper, garlic powder.
Granulated garlic?
Got it.
Cumin, chili powder,
paprika, salt -- not a lot --
Worcestershire,
apple-cider vinegar,
brown sugar,
and cloves.
Wow.
That's an interesting,
little twist.
We do tomato paste.
And where do all the recipes
come from?
It's where I keep
all my good stuff.
Cola.
We're gonna let it go
for about 45 minutes
to an hour.
We've got
a beautiful chuck roast.
I do a dry rub first, and
then we do some "Worcestshire."
Worcester-[mumbles]
Worcester-sure-shar-shire.
And then the oatmeal stout.
All right.
In the oven. What temp?
350 for about 3½ hours.
We let it cool,
and then we pull the roast.
Take the Texas toast,
and I use
Swiss and Muenster.
As in Herman.
Yes.
And then we've got our
caramelized onions and garlic,
and then we're gonna
put a little bit of
our beef on the grill,
And we'll just let those heat up
just a little bit.
So, we put the grilled onions
on, put our roasted beef on,
a little of our barbecue sauce
on there,
and then a little bit
of our house-made cheese sauce.
Close it up. It's gonna do
its thing for a second.
Take this beauty off.
Meaty Cheesy Goodness.
Outrageous.
When there's juice dripping out
of a sandwich like that...
it's a rich piece of meat,
cooked the right way,
super-tender,
cheesy --
without question --
and the little touch
of the barbecue sauce.
I mean, the whole thing.
I want to call that one
Meaty Cheesy Greatness.
[ Imitates chicken ]
Bawk! Bawk!
You bite into it, and the meat
just explodes in your mouth.
It's super-flavorful.
MAN #2: If you want
meat sandwiches and burgers,
it's some of the best stuff
you can get around town.
Amazing.
Outstanding?
I love it, yeah.
You're just a big kid
that likes to eat.
I'm only 13.
Years old?
Yeah.
You can be this big
and look like you're 21,
if you come eat
at The Sandwich League.
[ Woman laughs ]
So, that's it for
this Flavor Town road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."