Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Unh!
...we're roadtripping
to Bean Town...
Dude,
that is smokin' hot.
...for a Boston-flavor
extravaganza.
I'd eat that
out of a shoe.
In the Allston neighborhood...
Check it,
don't wreck it.
...a true
"Triple D" mashup.
You are not
gonna believe this.
One kitchen,
two restaurants.
This is probably
one of the most confusing
"Triple D's"
I've ever been to.
With legit Mexican
to the left...
I don't like it at all.
...and a wicked gastropub
to the right.
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
This is funky.
And, in South Boston...
I like it.
...authentic Polish...
Oh, Yahtzee!
...with a menu straight out
of the mother country.
Real-deal,
O.G. "Triple D."
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here
in Allston, Massachusetts,
eh, about three miles
from downtown Boston.
Now, listen,
I love coming to the East Coast.
What do I get?
I get clam chowder,
I get lobster rolls,
clam cakes, tacos,
tostadas, you na--
[ Record scratches ]
Wait a second.
Tacos? Tostadas?
That's right.
This is Lone Star Taco Bar.
TOSTE:
Chicken-ranchero tostadas, up.
MAN:
Grilled street corn.
I don't know where else
I would find anything like this
in Boston.
Huevos rancheros.
It's the most authentic Tex-Mex
you're gonna find
anywhere in this part
of the East Coast.
Dropping two tostadas.
FIERI:
And their real-deal menu is
thanks to co-owner Max Toste.
I was obsessed
with Mexican food.
One of my good buddies
used to call me "The Maxican."
And in 2012,
this obsession became a reality
when he opened this joint
along with longtime pals
Aaron Sanders and Rian Wyllie.
MAN: It's really about
the environment
that Max and everybody
have created.
Everything on the menu is great.
WOMAN:
Barbacoa taco.
Beef barbacoa, we're gonna make
a taco out of it.
All right.
So, we're gonna make
our marinade for the brisket.
Brown sugar, salt,
mustard powder, cumin,
some ground coriander.
Wow.
Ground garlic.
This is habanero chili --
super hot.
Ancho chili.
Black pepper,
and there's a pinch of cinnamon.
Cinnamon?
Yes, sir.
And a can of beer.
So, we're gonna
mix this up.
We're gonna add it
to the brisket for...?
At least a day.
The smoke's for flavor
and not for cooking.
Okay, so we're going
to the smoker.
What kind of wood?
Hickory.
Let it go for how many?
Four hours.
We're out of the smoker.
Picked up a little perfume
of that.
All right.
So, the next step?
We're gonna just build
an easy little braise.
We've got chopped onion, garlic,
and crushed tomatoes.
Some cilantro sprigs.
Beef stock.
That you made?
In certain-deed we did.
"In certain-deed we did"?
In certainly-deed we did.
I'm still working
on the language part.
Oh, listen,
I'm having such a hard time
with the English language
everyday.
Yeah, I wish
we could just do clicks.
[ Clicks tongue ]
I had some coffee.
[ Laughs ]
This is ready
to go in the oven.
325°.
Four hours, come out.
It needs to cool a little bit,
and then we can shred it.
After you shred it,
leave it in its jus.
Exactly.
And I hear that you are making
your own tortillas.
Right.
That was a big part
of the flavor profile
we're looking for.
We've got our avocado crema,
nice and sour-creamy and lime-y.
Our barbacoa,
nice, ample pinch of that.
Grated Cotija cheese.
And then we made
some pickled red onion.
I'm gonna cut you
a fresh piece of lime.
Oh, am I the lucky one.
'Cause you're the lucky one.
So, you're not skimping
on the size by any means.
Dude, that is smokin' hot.
It's got everything.
You got
a handmade tortilla,
then you go
into this barbacoa...
which is rich
and seasoned perfectly
and tender and juicy.
The crema
on the bottom,
the sting
from the pickled onion.
Unh!
It's so juicy.
It has a nice, smoky flavor.
You make a mess of yourself,
but it's worth it.
Lone Star Taco Bar is a lot more
than just a taco bar.
It offers
a lot of different cocktails,
a lot of different food items.
Generally always get
the corn.
MAN:
Grilled street corn.
WOMAN:
Slathered in a garlic aioli
with a little bit of spice
in it.
The grilled street corn,
one of the things
I think works great
is by parcooking.
Little salted water?
Absolutely, yeah.
I find by blanching it
and then grilling it,
this kind of blooms the sugars,
makes it nice and sweet.
What does it do?
Bloom.
It blooms the sugars.
So, we're gonna make
the aioli for it.
We start
with heavy mayonnaise,
fresh-chopped garlic,
ancho chili powder.
Gonna use some pepper,
kosher salt.
This is grated
Cotija cheese.
Fresh cilantro.
And now we're gonna add
some of my favorite hot sauce --
Valentina Extra-Hot.
Fresh lime juice is key,
tons of it.
Gonna whisk this up
nice.
So, this comes
out of the water.
Gonna snap it in half.
Yep.
We're gonna hit it
with a little bit of oil,
pepper,
and then a bunch of salt.
Give it a quick toss
and then on the grill.
Just a little char?
Yeah,
we want a nice char.
We're gonna put our aioli
on the plate down first.
Corn's finished
on the grill.
Give it a little roll.
Street corn
if I've ever seen it.
Then we need a big pinch
of Cotija.
Yep.
I like that flavor.
Little shake of our ancho chili,
make it nice.
And then plenty of fresh lime
to squeeze over it.
Very nicely done.
This, with a little bit
of the mayo
and a little bit
of the cheese
and a little bit of lime
coming through there,
a little ancho
at the end of it,
this is real
Mexican street food.
Well done.
Thank you, man.
Just fantastic.
It's fresh.
WOMAN:
The aioli's great.
It's really garlicky,
but sweet.
I don't like it
at all.
I'm gonna continue
to not like this
over the entire commercial
that's coming up
in just a minute.
We're hanging out
at Lone Star Taco Bar
in Boston,
of all places.
Can we make another dish?
Let's do it.
All right. I'll be
passed out in the corner.
See you in a little bit.
FIERI:
Welcome back.
Hanging out
in the outskirts of Boston
at a funky little joint
called Lone Star Taco Bar.
Chef Max and I,
we've had fantastic barbacoa.
We had some Mexican street corn.
It was outrageous.
And he promised me
something,
again, in this true,
authentic style.
What do you got for me?
Our chicken-ranchero
tostada.
WOMAN:
Chicken tostada.
Which is my go-to
pretty much every time I come.
Gonna make ranchero sauce.
Nice, hot stockpot.
I'm gonna use
a little vegetable oil.
Some onions.
Like to put some salt
in there
to help them sweat down
a little bit.
Now we're gonna add
our dry ingredients.
Hit it.
Pasilla chili.
Guajillo.
My favorite.
This is straight-up
chili powder.
Comino?
Comino, oregano.
Dried thyme.
Chopped garlic,
black pepper.
Give it a stir.
Now that this has sweat down
a little bit,
we're gonna add our chopped,
roasted green pepper,
poblano chilies,
and red chili pepper.
Yeah, we leave the skins on,
we get rid of the seeds.
'Cause we're gonna run this
in an immersion blender?
No, leave it chunky.
This chunky?
This chunky.
It's funky when it's chunky.
And then
a little green chili.
And last but not least...
Chopped tomatoes.
A little sugar.
This is gonna cook
for at least 45 minutes.
Got it.
I'd eat that out of a shoe.
We're gonna take our boneless,
skinless chicken breasts
and we're gonna put
some of our ranchero sauce
that we made right on there.
We've got
some ancho chili again.
Cumin, black pepper,
granulated garlic,
some fresh lime juice.
And then we're gonna put
some chicken stock in
to get this braising.
And now it's ready
for the oven.
325, 350,
three and a half hours.
Great.
We're gonna take it
out of the oven,
then we're gonna shred it.
Sit in its jus.
Exactly.
Build our tostada.
We got our refried beans.
[ Whistles ]
Nice, big chunk
of that chicken ranchero.
Sliced napa cabbage.
Our friend Cotija again.
This is our crema.
There is our
chicken-ranchero tostada.
And that's all she wrote.
That's all she wrote.
Mm-hmm.
Perfect date food.
You got tremendous flavor.
It's not super spicy.
Super, super tender.
You kill it, man.
Cheers.
Thank you, buddy.
MAN: So flavorful.
It's always
really tender and juicy.
I am always recommending
Lone Star
and Deep Ellum at the same time.
[ Record scratches ]
FIERI:
Wait, wait, wait.
Deep Ellum?
I think I saw that
on the way in.
MAN: The two very unique,
different places
under sort of one roof, really.
FIERI: Like, uh, Siamese twins
attached at the kitchen.
This is Lone Star.
Yes, sir.
And this is a whole
nother restaurant...
That is an entirely different
restaurant.
...called Deep Ellum.
Called Deep Ellum, yeah.
Mexican street food,
and this is...?
Gastropub.
It feels so gastropub.
They're both
so dramatically different
as far as the food menu,
the cocktail menu.
WOMAN: But both Deep Ellum
and Lone Star
have really high-quality food,
really high-quality drinks.
FIERI: That's because both
are wrangled by the same dudes.
So, if you want to go from
Deep Ellum over to Lone Star
or vice versa, you have to go
outside and come around?
So I guess that's how
I got to roll, too.
[ Engine turns over ]
This is Deep Ellum.
[ Laughs ]
Pork belly, farro.
This is a staple
in the neighborhood.
So if you're from here,
you get it.
Yeah, for sure.
FIERI:
And they've been getting it
since the joint opened in '07,
with Chef Rian cranking out
off-the-hook bar food.
You can come and get a hot dog
or a pretzel
or you can come and have, like,
pork schnitzel.
Like, the full works.
What do you normally have
when you come here?
I have
the salmon sandwich.
What are we making?
House-cured
salmon sandwich.
Start us off.
Salt, sugar,
black pepper, fennel seed,
juniper berry,
chili flake.
Got it.
Bay leaf?
Bay leaf, just crumbled.
Lemon zest.
Okay.
Mix that up.
So that's our cure.
Got it.
Salmon fillet.
Remove the belly,
remove the skin.
Nicely done.
Holy foil, Batman.
Double layer of foil.
Spread half out.
That's half your cure.
Put down your fillet.
And then...
Huh?
What a team.
Okay,
so we're set with this.
Wrap it up tight,
back on the sheet tray,
in the cooler,
and that's all she wrote.
That's it.
I want to see
the unveiling.
24 hours in the walk-in.
All that moisture
comes out.
You are not
gonna believe this.
Check it,
don't wreck it.
Look at that.
All right,
so now we rinse it?
Rinse it.
Slice it.
Take our bagel,
buttered, griddled.
Caper-chive cream cheese.
Salmon.
Some bibb lettuce,
sliced tomato.
Side of homies.
Look at that.
That salmon
just by itself...
...is outrageous.
Toasted bagel,
the chive-and-caper
cream cheese,
it's lights-out, man.
Awesome.
Mmm!
Salmon sandwich.
It's fantastic.
I love it.
I'm very fussy on my fish,
and I find the salmon
to be really fresh.
This place is just a great place
to be and hang out.
Great atmosphere.
Listen,
we're hanging out
at Deep Ellum
in Allston, Massachusetts.
When we come back,
Chef's gonna introduce us to...
Chicken two ways.
Bok-bok!
FIERI:
Now, stick with me on this one.
I'm in Allston, Massachusetts.
We're at one kitchen serving
two side-by-side joints --
Lone Star Taco Bar
and a gastropub
called Deep Ellum.
This is probably
one of the most confusing
"Triple D's"
I've ever been to.
But it's definitely working
for the locals.
MAN:
One place has been too crowded,
I come next door,
I get a great experience.
WOMAN: It's really hard
to pick between the two
'cause they're both
just as good.
And right now, we're playing
chicken at Deep Ellum.
Chicken two ways.
[ Bell dings ]
FIERI:
One way cooked up confit-style,.
and the other linked up
into sausage.
Chicken two way.
Yes.
Is that the name?
That is.
You're, like,
a marketing genius.
I know.
I came up with
a chicken andouille sausage.
Andouille love it.
[and do we]
Okay, let's hit it.
Boneless, skinless
chicken thighs.
Chunk these up.
Next?
Rind-off pork belly.
We're gonna combine
the pork belly and chicken.
Now we add
our dry ingredients.
Minced onion?
Garlic, ground thyme,
clove,
marjoram, allspice,
Cayenne.
[ Whistles ]
Black pepper, salt.
And a little curing salt.
Yep.
Mix this all together.
Now we're gonna grind it.
This is where
the magic happens.
This is when it gets fun.
So, you run this out, link this,
natural casings.
That's it.
All right.
Then we'll go to the smoker.
What are we gonna smoke this in?
Apple.
Couple hours, 200 degrees?
Yep.
And we'll hold it cold,
re-heat it for service?
Yes.
So, the andouille sausage
is done.
Now this is chicken
the other way.
Yep.
We're gonna make our cure.
We have salt, sugar,
black pepper,
fresh thyme,
and lemon zest.
Now we rub the cure
onto the chicken thighs.
Let them sit overnight.
Rinse it.
Back in the pan.
Duck fat.
Throw it in the oven,
four hours.
At...?
300.
And to re-heat?
Chicken's seared on the flat top
and ready for service.
Give me some.
Grits with some aged
Vermont cheddar,
collards, confit thigh.
House-made,
smoked andouille.
Peach relish, some chives.
Ridiculous.
Chicken two ways.
It sounds unique enough,
but to make it yourself...
Sausage
is lights-out, dude.
It has the right amount
of spice,
the right amount of heat.
That tastes like
I'm at somebody's cook shack
in Louisiana in the backwoods,
hanging out and getting ready
to have some jambalaya.
I mean,
that is legit.
So, this is brined
for a day, then...
Cooked in duck fat.
It's outrageous.
Awesome, man.
Tender, rich,
salty, crunchy.
Sweet relish over the top.
That may say chicken two ways,
but it's flavor 10 ways.
Dude,
you're blowing it up.
Thanks.
MAN:
Chicken two ways.
WOMAN:
The sausage is kind of smoky.
I love the texture of it.
MAN: It's confit,
so the meat's pretty much
fall-off-the-bone,
but there's still a great crunch
to the skin.
This is the first time
in "Triple D" history
that we've ever done
side-by-side restaurants.
And you guys have nailed it.
Well, like I always say
on "Triple D,"
if it's funky,
I'll find it.
This is funky.
Up next on our Boston tour...
Delicious.
...Polish classics from a dude
who seriously knows his stuff.
You got to meet this cat.
And since
I'm in Kennedy country,
I'm teaming up
with my buddy Anthony Shriver
for a really cool cause.
I just love food.
It's a good thing to love.
So, I'm here
in the south side of Boston
in an area known as
the Polish Triangle.
Now, I'm here to check out
exactly what you'd expect --
a Polish restaurant.
But not just any
Polish restaurant.
We're talking about
one of the most real-deal,
authentic Polish restaurants
you'll find in Massachusetts.
This is Cafe Polonia.
The cabbage roll is ready.
WOMAN: The minute
you walk into that door,
the smells just overwhelm you.
You don't want to leave.
Kielbasa with hunter stew
for you, ma'am.
The menu is very, very close
to what my mother used to do.
FIERI: But here,
Dad's running the show --
Chef and owner
Teddy Barcikowski.
FIERI:
Why Polonia?
We called
all people Polonia.
They still living
outside the mother country.
So people that live outside
the mother country
are called Polonia?
Yeah.
I like it.
And before Teddy
was a Polonia,
he fought against communism
in the Polish air force.
Then he escaped the U.S.
with his family recipes,
opening this joint in '02.
Pierogi are ready to go.
I love the pierogi.
And that's one of the few places
that actually does it the real,
authentic way.
What are we
gonna make first?
We're gonna make first
the meat pierogies.
Let's go.
We have two kind of meat --
pork shoulder,
and we have
the chuck tender.
There's the pork,
then you're gonna add a little
bit of celery, parsley, leeks.
We have carrots,
we have bay leaves here.
Allspice.
Granulated garlic,
granulated onions.
Vegeta spices.
Vegeta.
You know what is this?
Vegeta is vegetable base.
Used tremendously
in Europe.
Yeah.
We have to bring to boil.
Let it simmer?
Yeah.
And how long
is this gonna cook?
One and a half hours.
Gotcha.
Now, we pull the meat
out of the vegetables.
Meat is finished.
Caramelized onions.
Now we're gonna grind
the mixture
that's gonna go
in the pierogi.
Yes.
Holy moly
that's coming out fine.
Onions.
Oh, Yahtzee!
Now we mix the meat.
Now we gonna roll out dough
for the pierogies.
You cut it
in three pieces...
...and we're gonna
roll it out.
Now we cover it with water.
Time to make
the pierogies.
Right in the middle?
Yeah.
Take all the air out.
Got it.
And then the cutter.
Let's put these
in the water.
Now, how long
have these cooked?
Three to five minutes.
Very nice.
Sour cream in the middle,
caramelized onion
with the bacon bits.
Parsley.
Gonna be hot.
Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
Very light, very tender.
When people say,
"Oh, pierogi."
They've had frozen,
not hand-made pierogies.
And if you try this,
it will change the way
you think of them.
Delicious.
Here's your pierogies,
ma'am.
The meat inside,
it's a little bit sweet.
The right amount of onions
they way they should be sautéed.
One of the reasons
I'm here in Boston
is for a program called
Best Buddies.
My buddy Anthony Shriver, he's
the founder of Best Buddies.
My buddy Dan Koppen
and my buddy right over here,
this is Chris.
Here's this awesome
program
that works with adults with
intellectual disabilities.
It's about pairing buddies
and athletes and chefs.
It's a great way to teach people
about the acceptance
of difference and diversity.
Let me ask first --
what'd you think of the pierogi?
I thought the pierogi
was fantastic.
I just love food.
[ Laughter ]
It's a good thing to love.
Yes, it is.
Do you think Dan's had
very many pierogies?
Yes.
I think he's had
a couple.
The knight cutlet ready to go.
MAN:
Teddy does an excellent job.
Brings out a lot of flavors
in the pork.
WOMAN:
I love the knight's cutlet.
It's crispy and stuffed
with all these goodies inside.
Now we're going to make
the what?
Knight's cutlet.
We cut the pork,
then we're gonna pound it.
Like earthquake
in California.
Yeah, it is.
For the filling,
we use the smoked ham,
slice of mushroom,
Swiss cheese,
with a couple slices
of the red pepper,
bacon on the top.
Pepper, garlic, salt.
So, we gonna make the roll.
Got it.
It's going in the egg wash
and bread crumbs.
Okay.
Okay, now we go
to the fryer?
Now we're gonna go
to the fryer.
How long?
10 minutes, 270 degrees.
Low and slow.
Yeah.
So it cooks all the way through,
nice and even,
and doesn't brown too fast.
Yes.
Okay.
[ Whistles ]
Sauerkraut.
You make the sauerkraut?
Yes.
Carrot salad.
Polish ice cream.
Very nice.
Do you love the potatoes?
We finish with gravy
on the cutlet.
Very nice.
Let's get right into this.
Tastes great.
For the amount of time
that you cooked it,
a lot of the flavor
of the mushroom and the cheese
and smoked ham comes through.
Way to go.
Mmm.
Thanks.
Knight's cutlet.
That thing is so juicy
that it just bursts in flavors.
I don't want to share it
with anyone.
I grew up in Poland,
so I come to Teddy
to have a good dish.
He's a great cook.
There's no doubt about that.
It's just the best.
[ Chuckles ]
You put a lot of time and care,
the way you handle the food.
You put a lot of heart in it.
All my energies.
If you come down here,
you got to meet this cat.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
That's right.
This is Lone Star Taco Bar.
With the stumble.
[ Laughter ]