Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Okay, that's
flat-out ridiculous.
...I'm parking the '68
on a Cincinnati street...
Good idea.
I come up with them
all the time.
...that's become
a real-deal restaurant row.
Don't ruin
your appetite.
Do I look like
that could happen?
First up...
That's a flavor
kaleidoscope.
...a joint dealing in
dynamite dogs...
Hot dogs are gangster.
...and big-time bites.
[ Muffled ] That's a new one
on "Triple D" right there.
Then right across
the street...
Wow.
...a modern Midwest take...
Ah!
...on a Mexican taqueria.
What do you guys
in Cincinnati know
about great
Mexican food?
Plus, up the block...
[ Cork pops ]
Yahtzee!
[ Laughs ]
Hey!
...a Belgian bistro...
Want a waffle?
Yeah!
...dedicated to doing it right.
This is the way to get
your kid up in the morning
on Sunday and have him
mow the lawn and wax the car
and shave the dog.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here in a city in Ohio
that was once called Porkopolis.
That's because it was
the largest pork-producing city
in the United States.
Well, a lot has changed
since the late-1800s,
but people still call it
Cincinnati.
Anyhow, in the area that
I'm standing in on Vine Street,
a few years ago
wasn't doing so well.
That's until
a group of restaurant rebels
decided to move in
and open some awesome eateries,
starting off with this one
right here at Senate.
Got a Trailer Park
and a Korean.
Well, they're known
for their hot dogs.
I'm having the Hello Kitty dog.
The names are catchy.
You can't get 'em anywhere else.
FIERI: And the big dog
behind it all
is chef and owner Daniel Wright
who opened this joint in 2010.
Got a poutine.
Basically what we do
is gourmet street food.
It's unlike anything
you've ever had.
Korean hot dog.
The Korean dog
is just a wonderful mixture
of so many flavors.
MAN:
It's a really nice combination
that, honestly,
I didn't see coming.
All right, so,
what are we gonna make first?
We're gonna do
some braised short ribs
for the Korean hot dog.
Okay, rock 'n' roll.
So, we're gonna get
our pans hot.
Hit it with a little bit
of olive oil.
We're gonna take these
nice boneless short ribs here.
Look at those.
Season them
with a little salt and pepper.
We are now going to heat
our rondo.
We place some olive oil
in there.
We're gonna add our mirepoix --
our onions, carrots, celery,
and a little bit
of garlic.
When you say mirepoix,
you mean mirepoix.
Oh, yeah.
A little bit of salt in there
to break those onions down.
As soon as these are seared off,
you drop it in the mirepoix.
Yeah. Pour a little bit
of that drippings in there.
Now I'm gonna deglaze
with a little red wine,
and I'm gonna pour that right
back over our short ribs here.
Then the thyme?
Yeah.
And we're gonna top it
with some house-made demiglace.
We're gonna put a couple
tablespoons of Sriracha,
just right into our braise.
Wrap it?
Yep.
In the oven.
450 degrees for 5 hours.
Dig it.
Wow.
Doctor?
Nice and rich,
smells fantastic.
Don't ruin
your appetite.
Do I look like
that could happen?
[ Laughs ]
Gonna shred it?
Yep.
Gorgeous.
What's up next?
We're actually gonna make
our kimchi now.
Great.
We have some Napa cabbage
that we blanched,
and then we have
our kimchi base here.
There's fermented fish
in there.
There's tomato.
There's red chilies.
We're gonna add
a little Sriracha here.
White vinegar
and a little bit of sugar.
You're gonna mix this up.
How long are you
gonna let this ferment?
At least a month.
I mean, when we make this,
we make giant batches of this.
Okay, so this is done.
Next up?
We're gonna take
our short rib that we braised.
Gonna add that
to a pan here.
Add that braising jus,
cook that down a little bit.
We're gonna take our bun
that we seared off here.
Nice bun.
Locally?
Yep, we have those
made locally.
The dogs are actually
made locally. That's our recipe.
This is gonna be
our harissa aioli.
Put some of our braised
beef short rib.
Take our kimchi here.
There's
the pickled cucumbers.
Little bit
of toasted sesame seeds.
We've gone from hot dog
to dinner.
These are definitely
a meal.
[ Laughs ]
Dude, I don't know
what to tell ya.
That's a flavor
kaleidoscope.
Rich, salty, sweet, tangy,
good snap to the dog.
The short rib by itself
is just dynamite.
The cabbage and the slaw
and the pickles, all fantastic.
This is outstanding.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
The Korean hot dog.
MAN:
What sells it for me
is that the kimchi --
Kimchi I love right now.
The hot dog is amazing.
Hot dogs are gangster.
They're very good.
It's a winner wiener.
[ Laughs ]
MAN: So much more than
a hot-dog place here at Senate.
This place was a catalyst
for a lot of the redevelopment
that we've seen around the area.
What was this joint
before you classed it up?
WRIGHT: Nothing.
There was absolutely
nothing in here.
It basically had hit
as low as it was gonna go,
and the only thing
it could do was go up.
I'm not sure that
this neighborhood
would be a neighborhood without
having Dan here and Senate.
It's definitely
not just a hot-dog place.
It's more about
a communal restaurant.
Booty and belly.
The booty and the belly,
yeah, it's great.
You got the sweet and the sour,
and who doesn't like pork?
I wouldn't advise picking it up
as a sandwich.
It requires a fork and knife.
This is the booty and belly
sandwich.
We are doing
a little braised pork belly
and a little braised
pork butt here.
So, these get seared
on both sides?
Then we're gonna add that
to our caramelized mirepoix.
Okay.
We're gonna deglaze
with some Kentucky bourbon ale.
Love it.
Gonna pour it right back over
our pork belly and our mirepoix.
And our spice mixture here?
That is a little
Szechuan peppercorn.
I love 'em.
Oh, they go crazy
on your tongue.
We add a little cinnamon stick
and a little star anise,
as well.
Love it.
We're gonna add chicken stock,
cover it with foil.
Roast off in the oven
for how long?
450 for about 4 hours.
I can already smell it.
Can't wait.
Let this cool down a little bit,
strain the jus.
Okay. Now we can put
the sandwich together.
So we're gonna take our pork
that we braised,
add it in a little pan here,
barbecue sauce.
And you make
your own barbecue sauce?
We do.
Braise in jus.
Just let it come together.
Yeah, just kind of let it
do its thing there.
I'm gonna take our nice
seared brioche bun for you.
You ready for this?
[ Whistles ]
Take a little of this
apple celery root slaw,
a little bit
of our sauce here.
I'm gonna squeeze
two of these guys on here.
Flat-out ridiculous.
What?
[ Laughter ]
[ Muffled ] That's a new one
on "Triple D" right there, hm?
All right, brother,
let me tell ya.
Nothing you do
is short on flavor.
The pork between the belly
and the butt --
fatty, tender, texture.
The barbecue sauce --
outrageous.
Delicious.
Thank you.
It is unexpected and fun.
It's a party in your mouth.
Wow, great food.
Really a pleasure.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Next up,
we're headed up the street...
That is awesome.
...for a European café...
FLECHET:
It's the Belgian way.
Everything that I
don't understand,
you call a Belgian way.
...that's literally
got me speechless.
So I'm still here on Vine Street
in Cincinnati, Ohio,
checking out
some killer "Triple D" joints.
Now, I'm in an area
known as OTR --
Over-the-Rhine.
There was a huge European
immigrant influence here,
so this place makes total sense,
and I've heard a lot about it.
This is Taste of Belgium.
Oh, I've never had anything
that I didn't love here.
Nutty crepe.
You're taking a step
out of Cincinnati,
and you're walking into
something completely different.
I was pleasantly surprised
because of the authenticity
of the dishes.
FIERI: That's due to owner
Jean-Francois Flechet...
Nicoise is up.
...who was raised
in a tiny Belgian village
before coming stateside,
opening this place in 2011.
His specialty here, what else,
the Belgian waffle.
Plain waffle.
Fruit-and-cream waffle.
I love these waffles so much.
They're crunchy on the outside,
but soft on the inside.
Do people understand
what a Belgian waffle is?
I think here, everybody calls
a waffle a Belgian waffle.
Right.
What we make
is very dense,
and it's made
from a thick dough.
Okay, well,
let's get after 'em, man.
So, we're gonna start
with the flour, salt, yeast,
Mix it up.
We'll add the butter.
Eggs.
Raining chickens.
Milk, vanilla.
And the key is this
compressed beet sugar,
and you cannot
find it locally,
so when I got started,
I cashed out my IRA,
and I bought
10 tons of sugar.
You got to be related
to my family somehow.
It has a special texture.
It has a special melting point.
That doesn't smell like
any waffle
dough, batter
that I've ever made.
This gets done mixing.
We portion it...
Mm-hmm.
...cut it...
...put it
in the holding tray,
It goes in the refrigerator.
Yes.
And then it goes
to the waffle maker.
That is awesome.
So you have somebody
make this thing for you.
The one that comes from Belgium,
really not sturdy enough.
This one,
you can bang it all you want.
So the sugar
still never dissolved.
Still just big chunks --
a lot of sugar.
We put two balls of dough
on the waffle iron.
And we just close it.
Gravity will do the work.
And then 3 minutes,
you're gonna get
a beautiful waffle.
Just serve in wax paper.
That's the way we --
That's the way you get it
in Belgium.
Belgium.
That's outstanding.
I love the little crystals
that you get.
You know, you get a little bit
of that crunch inside of there.
I mean, that's crazy.
This is the way to get
your kid up in the morning
on Sunday and have him
mow the lawn and wax the car
and shave the dog.
Want a waffle?
Yeah!
Fruit-and-cream
Belgian waffle.
Any other waffle you've ever had
in your life it put to shame.
This is my cousin Jeff
and his son T.J.
What did you think, TJ?
Whenever you bite into it,
it's not
the normal waffle.
You can just eat 'em plain.
You don't need any syrup.
FLECHET: Plain waffle.
Did you cook at home
in Belgium?
I never cooked a waffle
until I started the business.
That's awesome.
My background
is in computer science.
Computer program and a recipe
are very similar.
Yeah, no, they are.
The special steps,
you follow them.
FIERI: And his recipes
go way beyond the waffle.
Carbonnade is up.
The carbonnade's just got
kind of those smoky flavors,
just like comfort food, almost.
All right, so,
what are we making now?
We are gonna make
carbonnade.
What is carbonnade?
Traditional
Belgian beef stew.
Hit it.
Beef tallow.
FIERI: You got to love
some beef tallow --
you know, rendered beef fat.
Then let's add the onions.
Garlic.
Bacon.
We're gonna take it
off the heat...
So we can sear the meat.
...so we sear the meat --
exactly.
What type of meat?
It's a mix of top
and round chuck.
Got it.
Salt and pepper.
We add onion, garlic, and bacon
back in the pot,
stir it all together,
and add the flour.
Got it.
Gonna build a little roux
off of the fat.
Exactly.
The apple cider vinegar.
The beer.
Which type of beer is this?
It's a good dark ale.
Okay.
And then some Dijon.
This is what we call
in Belgian sirop de Liège.
Sirop...
...de Liège.
This is really the secret
of the dish.
They gather all the apples,
all the pear,
put them in a big container,
reduce it,
and we use that
as a natural sweetener.
And last but not least,
the bouquet garni?
Bouquet garni.
So, parsley, bay leaf,
thyme, and peppercorns.
Exactly.
And then we're gonna let it cook
for about an hour and a half.
We're gonna place
some frites on the plate,
serve the carbonnade.
Hmm.
And then we add just a little
bit of pickled onions,
and this is
our chipotle mayonnaise.
Mm.
It's tender,
but not falling apart,
and there's rich, dark
beer being used in there,
so you get that note.
And are you supposed to dip
the frites in the mayonnaise,
or you dip it in this,
or...
You can alternate.
Comme ci, comme ça?
Comme ci, comme ça.
It's not super heavy.
It's not overpowering.
Outrageous.
Carbonnade is up.
MAN:
It's made just like in Belgium.
I lived there for a long time,
and they nailed it.
To find a traditional
Belgian place like yourself
is outrageous.
We're hanging out
in Cincinnati
on Vine Street
at the Taste of Belgium.
You got to come back.
I think we're gonna
make pretzels,
and my recommendation would be,
add some beer cheese.
FIERI: Welcome back.
We're hanging out
in Cincinnati, Ohio,
at the Taste of Belgium,
and this man served me waffles
like I've never had before.
Out of bounds.
Chef, what are we making next?
We're gonna make
some Belgian pretzel.
Okay, get going.
Yeast, sugar, water.
Okay.
We're gonna give it a whisk,
get it bubbling,
and then add the beer.
Then the flour.
Salt.
And then we put
the dough hook in.
Argh, Captain.
How long
we let this go?
For about 8 to 10 minutes.
Then we portion it out.
and then
just cut through it.
Look at this.
And then we're gonna flatten it,
roll it.
Let me see this
little, funky knot you do.
It's the Belgian way.
Everything that I
don't understand,
you call a Belgian way.
Nobody knows the first thing
about Belgium, so...
Yeah, so you just say,
"Oh, that's how we do it
in Belgium."
All right, so,
we'll let these proof how long?
About two hours.
They get boiled,
brushed with egg wash,
and then put in the oven --
12 minutes at 425.
Now we're going to make...
Beer cheese.
We add cream cheese,
Swiss cheese,
smoked Gouda, cinnamon, nutmeg,
and then some heavy cream.
Put some water in there.
We're gonna put this
in the water in the oven?
That's correct,
so that it doesn't burn.
How long
is this gonna go in?
That's gonna go in
for about 20 minutes.
At?
350.
And we're gonna add
the beer.
What we use is a
raspberry-flavored Belgian beer.
Okay.
And it adds a very unique flavor
to the beer cheese.
I can imagine.
[ Cork pops ]
Yahtzee!
[ Laughs ]
Hey!
That's a party.
Did that make the Jumbotron?
[ Laughs ]
And then we're gonna
finish blending.
Serve that with a pretzel.
Good idea.
I come up with them
all the time.
Wow.
A little parsley.
So, what we're gonna do
with the pretzel
is brush
with a little bit of water
and put some coarse salt on.
The texture on the pretzel
is real authentic.
Great crust on it.
I mean,
it just smells great.
The beer cheese is rich,
super flavorful.
Do not think you're getting,
you know,
a side of nacho cheese
dipping sauce.
This is a meal.
Outstanding, sir.
Very nice job.
Thank you.
WOMAN: I love the Belgian
beer cheese and pretzels.
It's crunchy on the outside,
chewy on the inside.
Blows us away.
We have it often.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the famous Jeff Ruby.
Jeff has a fantastic group
of restaurants
in the Cincinnati area.
They do a great job,
and the food's terrific.
MAN: It's nice to see
such an interesting and unique
restaurant down here.
We're just happy
to have him.
When you walk through
those doors off of Vine Street,
you got to kind of
catch yourself and look around
because you're
in another country.
Thank you, thank you.
This is really
a great experience.
FIERI: Up next,
one more stop on Vine...
That pile
will make you smile.
...with a legit
Cincinnati take...
Nice!
...on the taco?
Outstanding.
Let's make a taco.
So I'm here in Cincinnati
on Vine Street.
Now, this area has had
a lot of ups and downs
throughout the years,
but they're definitely
on their way back up,
with all these cool restaurants
that are opening in the area
like this joint
where they're serving up
Mexican street tacos.
This is Bakersfield.
Table 8, pastora,
cochinita, two fish.
WOMAN:
I like to eat a lot of tacos.
I like to drink a lot of beer.
So I get to come here
and do just that.
It's a little more
of a Southwest style of food.
FIERI:
That south-of-the-border concept
was the brainchild of brothers
Joe and John Lanni
and good buddy Alex Blust
who opened this place in 2012.
[ Record needle scratches ]
What do you guys
in Cincinnati know
about great
Mexican food?
We wanted to be approachable,
affordable, and fun.
We thought tacos would be
a really good vehicle for that.
FIERI: And the man behind
these tantalizing tacos
is Chef Chas Barracato.
Two short-rib tacos.
WOMAN: Mainly, I just stick
to the short rib
'cause they're just so good.
It's a meatiness going on,
and then you got that radicchio,
which is bitter, just to cut it.
It all equals out
and tastes awesome.
What are we gonna make?
We are going to make
our short-rib marinade
for our short-rib tacos.
Give me the rundown, man.
First, we're gonna take
our roasted tomatoes.
All right.
Come on, get up there.
Ah!
Got beef stock,
chipotle chili.
In adobo, very nice.
Tomato paste.
Whole garlic.
Brown sugar.
And kosher salt.
So, what's the next step?
We're gonna braise
our short ribs.
Okay, so, all we're gonna do
is hit it with salt and pepper.
Wow.
So, the goal here
is to just sear each side,
get great crust
all the way around.
BARRACATO: Absolutely.
All right, buddy, next.
We're gonna add cinnamon sticks,
a few bay leaves.
Let's add the marinade.
Now, how long are we gonna
let this braise in the oven?
We're gonna cook it at 350
for about 4 1/2 to 5 hours.
Take it.
Look at that.
Let's make a taco.
Okay.
Look at this thing.
Then we're gonna take
our braising liquid,
a pinch of salt,
a pinch of pepper,
some of our fresh
tortillas.
We're gonna take
our shredded short ribs.
And hit with crema
and queso fresco.
Pickled white onions.
FIERI: Cilantro.
And then we're gonna finish it
off with slices of radish.
It's got a lot of street taco
going right there.
The tortilla is very light.
The short rib, it's tender,
not overseasoned.
Love the cinnamon
in there.
This is a really
elevated taco.
I mean, the whole thing
comes together fantastic.
Mm.
Two short-rib tacos.
They're nice and juicy.
They've got a nice crunch to it.
MAN:
Finished on a corn tortilla.
It doesn't get
more authentic than that
in the middle of the heartland.
So you guys are making
handmade tortillas?
Absolutely.
We usually do
about 2,000.
Every day?
Every day.
FIERI: But it's not
just tortillas and tacos here --
No, they're also turning out
the tortas.
Milanesa torta.
WOMAN:
I had the chicken milanesa.
It's my favorite sandwich.
It's something with the bread.
It's a nice, crispy
chicken cutlet.
What are we up to now?
Our chicken milanesa torta.
Okay.
Gonna take water
to start off.
Honey, kosher salt,
black pepper, bay leaves.
We've got our seven-ounce
chicken breasts here.
How long is this chicken
gonna brine?
Minimum 24 hours.
All right, so,
the chicken's brined.
We're gonna pound the breasts.
Next we're gonna take
our egg wash,
put it into the bread crumbs.
Let the bread crumbs
adhere to it, and then --
Yes, we're gonna let 'em go
for about two hours.
And then this is gonna go
to the fryer?
Yes.
Ready to rock.
Fried chicken breast.
Take our telera roll,
add black bean spread
to the bottom of it.
Take our fresh
tomatillo salsa.
Put a line
right down the center,
chicken breast on top.
Dig it.
We're gonna hit it
with a little dressed
arugula salad with some lemon.
That pile
will make you smile.
Avocado mayo.
And now we're gonna go
to the panini press.
Absolutely.
Just gonna cut it
on the bias.
Get our plate.
Gonna serve it
with a little tomatillo salsa.
Big torta.
The flavor
that's going on in here,
you're not getting
a big fried-chicken sandwich.
Right.
You're getting
a thin, crisp, tender chicken
using the bean spread --
genius.
The arugula
and the tomatillo salsa,
I mean,
it's what ties it all together.
It's really good, man.
Appreciate it.
Anything with black bean,
I love.
It's got that little peppery
flavor with the arugula.
Your chicken milanesa.
I would give this place a 10.
FIERI: Maybe that's because
Joe and John learned the ropes
from a true restaurant vet.
That's right, their dad, Nick.
You've been in the business
for how long?
Since I was 14.
It's one of the greatest joys
a parent can have in life,
to have your children
do what you did
and be really successful
at it.
There is a wait all the time,
but you just have to be patient.
You just have to know
that it's gonna happen.
And once it happens,
you're in heaven.
It's rockstar.
Nice job, Chef.
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Have we ever
been to jail together?
Uh, no comment.
No Comment, that's exactly
where I thought we were.
No Comment's in Utah.
It's a small little town
right outside of Salt Lake.