Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ohh!
...we're going old school...
This is, like,
old-school old school.
...looking for joints that
are cranking out the classics...
I think that's why they've been
in business almost 100 years.
...on Brigantine Island,
New Jersey...
This is the kind of place
people would love to have.
...a throwback butcher shop...
I like the knife skills, man.
You're right after it.
...keeping
a meaty tradition alive...
Real deal.
Appreciate it.
...In Leeds Point,
New Jersey...
We are in the middle
of nowhere.
...a decades-old landmark...
I'm gonna give you
some points right there.
...where the menu rocks,
and the view is top-notch.
I'll be back.
All right, very good.
All I got to do
is get a boat.
...and in Des Moines, Iowa...
That's...
Money.
...a legendary
All-American drive-in...
He's been doing it
62 years here.
...where chili
still reigns as king.
That's the best
I've ever had.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Be right with you.
Thank you.
So, listen, you guys
are saying it all the time --
"Guy, the name of the show is
'Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives,'
and we don't see
many drive-ins anymore."
Well, that's the sad truth.
There's not many left.
So,
I'm here in Des Moines, Iowa,
and I hear they've got
a legendary drive-in
that's owned by royalty.
You know I got to check it out.
This is George the Chili King.
It's the classic
American drive-in.
MAN: It reminds you
of "American Graffiti,"
"Happy Days."
Food is exactly what you would
expect from a place like this.
It's old-fashioned.
It's good.
Chili up.
What makes
George the Chili King so great?
Well,
George is number one.
FIERI:
Actually, he's number two.
George Karaidos' dad,
George Sr.,
was the first to open
a chili joint
after winning a local contest
nearly a century ago.
The Des Moines Register crowned
him "George the Chili King."
FIERI:
Started in 1920 downtown.
Opened this one,
made you take it over
when you were 19.
Yes.
He's been doing it
62 years here.
That's correct.
George the Chili King
is a Des Moines institution.
His chili is the best-tasting
in Des Moines.
I get it at least
once a week, every week.
Seriously?
Seriously.
FIERI: Now, was this
your dad's recipe?
Yes, it was.
And this pot
came off a battleship.
I see "U.S." something.
And the year
-- 1944.
'44. That's crazy.
We start out with suet.
Ground-beef fat.
Uh-huh.
So, we wait till
this renders down.
Yeah.
Then we drop the meat.
Right.
Look at that beautiful
ground chuck.
Look at that.
Ground chuck.
You look like you've done this
before for maybe 60 years.
All right, George,
we've cooked down.
Yeah, now we add
the spices.
There goes
the chili powder.
Cumin?
Uh-huh.
Ground allspice.
Granulated garlic.
To give it
that I-talian taste.
That I-talian taste.
[ Chuckles ]
A little salt.
Wow, there we go.
A little cayenne pepper.
George is pretty liberal
with the spices here.
Okay, now we put
the cracker meal in.
Cracker meal's going in.
In the pot now.
I'm trying to, George.
I'm dusted right now
by the cracker meal.
I can't even see.
I got to wear goggles over here.
[ Coughs ]
Good job.
Thank you, George.
Now, this cracker meal
gives it the body.
Kind of like a gravy.
Now, see,
this is pretty dry.
I got ahold of her.
Yeah.
So add more suet.
When in doubt,
pour more fat in.
Yeah.
You're at a ratio of about
65%-35% fat to meat.
I think that's why they've been
in business almost 100 years.
We put it in a pan
like this.
We add water and beans.
When we get to this point,
we're done.
We're done.
It's got, like, a little bit
of a gravy consistency.
Yeah.
I put crackers. I can't
eat it without crackers.
Yeah, got to have
some crackers.
A little bit of cheese?
You go cheese?
Yeah, a little bit
of cheese.
All right, I want to make sure
I do it the right way.
I don't want
to be the new guy.
Can I have
some of these onions?
You sure can.
Just help yourself.
I'm a two-scooper.
All right.
Mmm. Oh, yeah.
It's a very rich chili.
Very deep.
Very flavorful.
Without question.
The beans also work into that
velvety smooth texture.
People who come in here
must go nuts for this.
They're addicted to it.
I am.
You drive by
a joint like this,
and you know that there's
a character like this cat.
This is the Chili King.
You got to try it.
You bet.
That's my man.
[ Laughter ]
The chili is fantastic.
It's kind of gravy-like
and spicy.
MAN: Everybody comes here
for the chili,
but I like mine on a dog.
I love
the Hamburger Coney Style.
Is that your car
out front?
Uh-huh.
That '34?
Oh, with the rumble seat
in the back?
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Ohh!
Would you trade it
for your Camaro?
Well, I like the way
you think, buddy.
I'm getting hustled
by the hustler.
[ Laughs ]
You come for the nostalgia,
but you wouldn't come at all
if the food wasn't good.
MAN:
The chili is awesome,
and the tenderloins
are to die for.
KARAIDOS:
Tenderloin up.
Every time
I come to Des Moines,
people tell me I got to try
this one particular sandwich --
One of the staples
in Iowa.
When we come back,
I'm hanging out with
George the Chili King
here in Des Moines, Iowa.
You've got to come back
and see what we're gonna make.
That's right.
You're the man.
I'm the man.
See you in a bit.
That's a good onion ring.
KARAIDOS:
Oh, thank you.
They're made from scratch,
homemade right here.
Here at George the Chili King's
in Des Moines, Iowa.
Now, we just had
some fantastic chili
with a whole bunch
of stories.
Almost 100 years of business
going on here.
When you come into town,
they talk about
this tenderloin sandwich.
This is
a Des Moines, Iowa, staple.
Right.
Here you have
your tenderloin.
Absolutely wonderful.
It's breaded beautifully,
fried just right.
When I do want tenderloin,
I will come here every time.
This is a pork butt.
We make the pork tenderloins
out of this.
We're gonna cut some meat
off of this.
And this is how
your dad taught you?
That's right.
Now we're gonna take this
and run it through
the tenderizer-o-matic.
Let's get her
going here.
Ooh.
Fold it over.
And I notice how you're
just dropping it.
I don't want
my finger in it.
That's why he just
chucks it in.
Yeah.
That's all she wrote.
We're gonna bread it.
Put some buttermilk in here.
That's a new bowl.
That come off
the Battleship Iowa.
Don't start with
your one-liners, George.
You already stole my show.
[ Laughs ] I'm sorry.
Put this in here,
and put a little cracker meal
over there.
And we roll it.
Now you roll it.
Okay, George,
let me get in here.
That's enough.
Not too hard.
Okay, not too hard.
Wow, look how big it got.
Whoa!
Just dump it right in there.
Just drop it right in?
Okay, there we go. Just float it
in there nice and light?
Oh, yeah.
We'll put a little
ketchup on.
Some onions, too.
A few onions,
some pickles.
And we'll put
the mustard on this.
Mustard on top?
Yeah, mustard on top.
That's good, isn't it?
Check that out.
It might not be the biggest one
in town, but it's the best one.
Is that good or what?
Hot.
Hot. Yeah, I forgot to tell you
it just came out of the fryer.
[ Laughter ]
Mmm.
I know that we say that
it's the tenderloin,
but it's pork butt.
I use pork butts because
they have more flavor.
If you didn't tell somebody
it wasn't a tenderloin,
they wouldn't know.
Yeah.
That really is
the key, George.
And it's tons of flavor.
Nice bun. Toasted.
You don't overdo it.
Simple, straightforward,
quality.
You know what
that is, George?
That's...
Money.
That's money, George.
That's money.
It's a good tenderloin.
It's big. It's hearty.
It's got the best
crispy outer coating ever.
You guys are lucky.
Everybody in the country
is envious of what you have
here in Des Moines.
And it's owned by royalty.
He is the king!
It's just one of those things
that doesn't change.
You're the man.
You're the man, too, bud.
[ Laughter ]
That's the best
I've ever had.
FIERI:
Coming up in New Jersey...
You like to eat.
I like to eat.
...a Brigantine Island
butcher...
Smell the aroma.
[ Laughs ]
...making jerky
people are jonesing for.
Cheers.
Did you just "cheers" me
to eat jerky?
Uh-huh.
You know what
you don't see anymore
is drive-in movie theaters.
I mean,
they're just not around.
Record stores --
You don't see those.
And butchers --
old-school butchers.
You know, the ones where
they're making the sausage,
and they're grinding it --
the whole real deal.
You just don't see them anymore.
Well, that's unless
you're here on Brigantine Island
right over the bridge
from Atlantic City, New Jersey.
Oh, you got to check it out.
This is Ernest & Son.
CORTELLESSA:
Turkey club!
Everything's fresh.
Thank you, man.
Thanks for coming in.
WOMAN: The quality
and the consistency
really does set it apart
from other places.
Four minutes on the burger.
This is the first stop on
the island when we come home.
So, when you're
coming into town...
Got to hit Ernest.
FIERI: And the guy
behind the counter
is owner and butcher
Mel Cortellessa,
who took over the place in '07,
30 years after
it originally opened.
Bro, this is, like,
old-school old school.
Who started this?
CORTELLESSA: Ernie Storino
was the original owner.
His son, Sam,
is who I started with.
I started when I was 13,
sweeping up, putting
groceries on the shelves,
and fell in love with it.
My dad and I started the store,
and I felt very comfortable
turning the store over to Mel
and know that the tradition
will carry on.
So, you're doing, like,
real butchering here.
We do beef, veal, lamb,
pork, fresh chicken.
Canned liver.
We do everything.
WOMAN: I don't get my meat
from the grocery store.
I get it only here.
Guys, why don't you try some
jerky? It's homemade.
MAN: This is the only place
that I know of
that makes homemade jerky.
WOMAN:
My kids love it.
They take it by the handful,
and it's done within the hour,
and we have to come back.
All right, so,
what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
a mild beef jerky.
We're gonna take
our bottom round.
Also known
as the gooseneck.
We're gonna cut it in half
and get our piece.
And we're gonna trim it up.
I like the knife skills, man.
You're right after it.
It's all I've ever done.
It's a skill, brother.
So, we got it all
stripped up and nice.
Okay.
We got a little liquid smoke.
That's what
we start off with.
All right.
Love it.
Soy sauce.
[ New Jersey Accent ]
Curry.
What was that?
This is curry.
"Carrie"?
You know her, don't you?
We got onion powder,
and then you got
curry's sister, ginger.
You know her, don't you?
All right,
we're going in with ginger.
All right, so,
we're mixing it up,
sprinkling it on.
Okay.
We have honey.
Then we add
a little brown sugar.
Okay.
Then you got
the Jamaican jerk sauce.
So, we're gonna mix it up.
All right.
Are you known
for your jerky?
I mean, do people come in and
go, "Got to get some jerky"?
I don't know anyone else
that makes it around here.
Okay, let it go, then we'll
go to the dehydrator?
Yep.
Jerky's been marinating
24 hours.
It's been what?
Marinating.
Okay, you ready?
We're gonna lay it out.
And we're gonna let it go how
long, did you say?
15 to 20 hours.
So, now we're gonna
turn it on.
Smell the aroma.
[ Laughs ]
All right, so, now we got
the jerky ready to eat.
Did you put
anything else on it?
No.
That's just what happens?
That's what happens.
Cheers.
Did you just "cheers" me
to eat jerky?
Uh-huh.
It's not too dry,
not over-seasoned.
There's some nice
balance to it.
A little hot,
a little sweet, right?
Yeah.
That's good jerky.
Great jerky.
I'm gonna have another piece.
[ Laughter ]
The jerky is something that's
great for tailgating parties.
MAN:
It's delicious,
and he has it from
the spiciest you can handle
to the more subtle, soft taste.
And the jerky isn't the only
draw at this joint.
We're a seasonal community.
So summertime,
it's heavy on the sandwiches.
600, 700 rolls in a day.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Big sandwiches,
a lot of meat.
Tailgater.
It's the sausage-pepper sandwich
with cheese on it.
He makes his own sausage.
The spices, the flavors,
you can really taste that.
All right, what are we into?
Some pork butt?
CORTELLESSA: We're making
Italian mild sausage
for the Tailgater sandwich.
And we're gonna grind it.
You ready?
We're not gonna put
any seasoning on them?
No, we grind first.
Maybe that's my secret.
All right, you ready?
I'm ready.
Here we go.
We're gonna throw it
up top and re-grind.
Okay, so,
you grind it twice?
Right, because it's a better
mixture and a better look.
Got it.
Here's our ground Boston butt.
Ready for a little seasoning.
Okay.
Paprika.
Nice little color.
A little black pepper.
Salt.
And this is my favorite.
This is fennel.
I don't get the seeds.
I get it crushed.
Got it.
Smells like Good & Plenty.
Remember the candy
Good & Plenty?
It's licorice.
It's my favorite
candy, too.
[ Whistles ]
Then we're gonna mix it.
Are we using
natural casings?
Natural casings.
Okay.
Now we roll.
Awesome.
Let it set overnight.
Got it.
And we'll take a piece.
And we're gonna drop
the sausage in the deep fryer.
Get the grill going.
Now we're gonna start frying
the green peppers and onions.
We're gonna do it up with
a little salt and pepper.
Let that start cooking.
We're gonna add the sausage.
I like to cut
the sausage open,
give it a little [hisses]
on the inside.
A little what?
[ Hisses ]
Got some domestic
sharp provolone.
Once the cheese is all melted,
we put it in the roll,
and it's ready to eat.
There's the Tailgater.
That's how you do it.
That's how we do it.
That's good sausage, man.
That's really good sausage.
Thank you.
The key is that fennel.
You think?
Oh, and it gets great flavor
all the way through it.
And I like the fact
that you let it set for a day
before you cook it.
Sure.
The bread is nice.
It's tender,
but it holds together.
Salty provolone.
Good, right?
Sharp provolone.
You like to eat.
I like to eat.
Real deal. I love it.
Appreciate it. Thank you.
Tailgater.
The sausage
are very, very tender.
The cheese is sliced right here
in the shop.
Fresh rolls every day.
Thank you.
Have a good day.
To have this on the island
is special.
And it's just a dying art.
The fact that you're making it,
you're cutting it,
and you're butchering it,
and just all these components,
I see why, when people walk in,
they go,
"I want to have you
in my neighborhood."
Yeah.
This is the kind of place
people would love to have.
Not many of us left.
Not many.
FIERI: Up next...
Bubble?
...across the bay
in Leeds Point, New Jersey...
Did you pick that up?
...a 1930s joint
where the clams jam...
I could eat
a thousand of those.
...and the shrimp sizes up.
Whoa!
That's a monster.
I'm here at the end of the road.
No, not in a negative way.
I'm literally
at the end of the road.
I'm in Leeds Point.
I'm like 20 miles away
from Atlantic City...
I know. Atlantic City.
...to check out a joint where
they've been serving it up fresh
since 1938.
We're talking three generations.
This is the Oyster Creek Inn.
Got two Jersey Devil Shrimp
in two minutes.
There's no disappointment here,
especially if you love seafood.
I work all week to look forward
to coming here on Friday.
Scallop app.
Delicious. Incredible.
Oyster Creek is like
stepping back in time.
'Cause this local legend
has been in the same family
for nearly seven decades,
with owner Bill Kuppel
taking the reins from his dad
in 2003.
We are in the middle
of nowhere.
Yep.
Been here since 1930s,
before the federal government
bought up all this property
as a wildlife refuge.
FIERI: These days, Bill's sons
are carrying on the legacy.
Jason's behind the bar.
And to quote my buddy Emeril,
Scott's kicking things up
a notch in the kitchen.
Clams Mexicali
in the window.
I just fell for
the Clams Mexicali.
It's one of Scott's
special creations.
You're not gonna find them
anywheres else.
What are we making?
We're gonna make
our Clams Mexicali.
We're about as close
to Mexico...
Well, I used to live
in California,
so I adopted the name.
Where?
Well, I was stationed
at Camp Pendleton.
Oh, in the military?
Yes, sir.
Thank you for
your service, man.
Thank you.
Where are the clams from?
Great Bay,
right outside the restaurant.
They come up to the dock
right here.
What kind of clams
are these?
These are choice
top neck clams.
Choice?
Choice top neck.
It's a certain size.
How do you know?
The clammer tells me.
The clammer tells you.
He knows his clams.
All right, we steam these
for about 12 minutes.
We put them in an ice bath,
cool them down.
So they stop cooking.
So they're not gonna
get all tough on us.
All right,
now what are we doing?
Now we're gonna make
the meat filling.
We're gonna start
with some butter.
These are drippings
from chorizo.
All right. Next up?
Throw in the red peppers
and then the diced jalapeños.
You know, I'm gonna give you
some points right there.
You said it correctly.
Well, I'm from Mexico.
You're not from Mexico!
[ Laughs ]
Dump that in.
Browned chorizo.
And fresh bread crumbs.
Roasted poblanos.
Chopped up cilantro.
We're mixing this up,
and then we're gonna cool it
for about 10 to 15 minutes.
Mm-hmm. Now?
We're gonna add the cheese
to our cool chorizo mix.
Okay.
This is a longhorn cheddar.
Clams ready to be stuffed.
Are we putting them
in the broiler?
in the oven?
We put them in our convection
oven for about eight minutes.
Cheese will start to bubble,
and they'll be ready to roll.
What will happen?
The cheese will start
to bubble.
Did you pick that up?
Bubble?
Bubble.
Take the Clams Mexicali
out of the oven,
put them on the plate.
Little bit of parsley.
It's salty.
A little bit spicy.
Great clam flavor.
You know how to say
"jalapeño" correctly.
[ Laughter ]
Got a nice amount
of peppers in there.
Clam's not overcooked.
I could eat
a thousand of those.
A thousand?
Oh, that'll be $1,000
'cause they're
a dollar apiece, so...
[ Laughter ]
Clams Mexicali.
I've had the Clams Mexicali
many times.
There's a lot of things
in that little dish.
They're delicious.
You can't beat them.
FIERI: You can't beat
the location, either.
The view is awesome.
FIERI: And it's bringing
people in by the boatload.
We've had over 60-foot boats
tied up at the restaurant.
Really?
To see all this wildlife,
along with beautiful sunsets,
it's incredible.
People just come in by boat,
come in by car.
We come by motorcycle.
Or by motorcycle.
There's not many other places
like this in New Jersey.
FIERI:
And good luck finding this dish
anywhere else
in the Garden State.
Jersey Devil Shrimp
in the window.
Scott's spicy take on shrimp,
named for the state's
infamous hellion.
They're so good,
you eat every bite.
And they taste incredible.
Okay, so, we're making
the hot sauce for the --
Jersey Devil hot sauce.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Start with red hot sauce.
This is our pepper extract.
Green hot sauce.
Worcestershire sauce.
Dude, what?
What was that, son?
[ Laughing ] Worces-- Wor--
Now I can't say it.
Onion powder.
Caribbean jerk seasoning.
Garlic powder.
Scorpion powder.
What is
the scorpion powder?
Scorpion powder is powder
from a scorpion pepper.
Brown sugar.
Gonna stir it up,
and we're gonna let it simmer
for 10 to 12 minutes.
Add the butter.
Blend it all together.
Ready for service.
All right.
We're gonna bread
our shrimp for frying.
Whoa!
It's a monster.
It's a U/8 colossal shrimp.
I haven't eaten it yet,
but I will.
[ Chuckles ]
Start in the flour,
evaporated milk,
back to the flour.
Now we fry them?
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
All right.
When the sauce is hot,
what do we do?
We drop it right in the bowl
with our shrimp.
Okay.
Put them on the plate on top
of our homemade coleslaw.
We dump the Jersey Devil sauce
right on top.
And then a little parsley.
It's fantastic.
Not too much breading.
Nice little spice to the sauce.
It's not wing sauce.
There's a little bit
of sweet to it.
The slaw is nice
and crunchy and vibrant.
It's simple. It's tasty.
Cool, little appetizer.
And I say "little,"
but a lot of flavor
'cause of that
big U/8 shrimp.
U/8 -- eight of them
to a pound.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Jersey Devil Shrimp.
First of all,
the shrimp are monsters.
You could almost pass them off
as a little lobster tail.
It all just joins together
really well.
The food's phenomenal.
The atmosphere's phenomenal.
The view is incredible.
Oyster Creek is definitely
an ideal destination for dinner.
I'm telling you something,
man, I'll be back.
All right, very good.
All I got to do
is get a boat.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip.
But don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
I'm George the Chili King,
and you're watching
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
Me and George
hanging out.
We're gonna go do burn-outs
in the Camaro.
[ Chuckles ]
That's money,
and I'm the man.
[ Laughter ]