I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, my gosh, man.
This is crazy.
...we're traveling
the country...
This is gonna be awesome.
...looking for a true taste
of the world.
I don't know that I'm gonna
be able to eat all of it,
but I'll sure try.
In Cincinnati, Ohio...
You're an amazing cat.
...the Jamaican joint...
Yeah, mon.
...turning up the heat...
You sweating?
Oh, yeah.
...on some real-deal
island eats.
It's like an offering
to the gods.
All right.
In Duluth, Minnesota...
My new job.
...the corner Thai spot...
This is
the American dream.
...putting full-on flavor...
Delicious.
...right in their fusion.
Look at how pretty
that is.
And in Boston, Massachusetts...
That's a nice dough.
...we're jumping off
at Italian central...
If you don't eat that, you're
out at the next stop, bro.
...where the whole family's
along for the ride.
Chew, chew.
[ Laughter ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here on Water Street --
or around here,
they say "watah" --
because I'm in the financial
district of Boston,
and I'm here to check out
what may look like
your average,
everyday pizza joint.
But from what I hear,
behind these walls
is real-deal Italian.
This is Casa Razdora.
Rotelle Patrizia.
MAN: It's a surprise.
It almost looks like a deli
from the outside.
Bistecca.
We may as well be in Italy.
WOMAN: When you see
these beautiful pictures,
it really just feels
authentic to me.
Rosette, pasta pesce.
FIERI: That's because
when Denise Santini
and Giancarlo Baldini
opened in 2010,
they made it all about
their Italian family.
You marry
an Italian guy...
I did.
...you bring him back,
you get connected
with your cousin Bobby...
Yeah.
...and you guys open
this joint.
Absolutely.
And while Denise
runs the front...
You'd like the rosette?
Wonderful.
...the boys cook up
traditional dishes in the back.
Porcini cascioni.
It's an interesting take
on a sandwich.
It's got mushrooms in there.
It's got the cheese.
WOMAN:
It's thin and flat and crispy.
This is very nice.
We're gonna make
a porcini cascioni.
All right.
I'm gonna add the sausage.
And I'm gonna brown this
a little bit.
We're gonna add
some butter, shallots,
and we're gonna mix this up
a little bit.
Now, this was full
when I showed up here earlier.
That's right,
I had a couple.
And that's about right,
right there.
I really like
your measurement skills.
It's right
on the money, bro.
All right,
button mushrooms.
With this in there,
I'm gonna add porcini mushrooms
that have rehydrated.
There we go.
We're gonna put
the steeping juice, as well.
Exactly.
All this cooks down?
Cooks down roughly
35 minutes or so.
Meanwhile,
we'll make the dough.
You got it, bro.
Word.
Ready to roll.
We're gonna put
the A.P. flour in here.
Baking powder.
I'm gonna add a little milk
and salt water mixed.
Sunflower oil.
Okay.
I'm gonna close it up.
Do this for about
seven minutes or so.
That's a nice dough.
7-ounce balls,
I hope.
Here we go.
8.5
8.5.
Ooh!
You're heavy.
7.8.
Ooh!
Oh, I beat you!
I beat you!
Now what do we do?
Now we're gonna bring it
to the roller.
When you often come over to this
area, do you wear a necktie?
I was hoping you would.
You, listen.
[ Laughs ]
You don't think
I've done this a few...
No, I bet you have.
There you go.
All right, good.
Vamos. Right here.
All right.
We're gonna stuff it
with porcini mixture.
Paul Bunyan
coming for dinner?
Now a little gorgonzola,
like this.
A little aqua.
Around, around.
Flip the sucker over,
like this.
Gonna press it down
a little bit.
Crimp it.
Ready for the flattop.
My mouth is watering.
I love porcini mushrooms.
Mm!
This would be close to
an Italian quesadilla.
The dough is light --
a lot like a flour tortilla.
The filling
is outrageous.
The shallot, the sausage --
Boy, it's good.
You nailed it, buddy.
Thanks, bro.
Great job.
WOMAN:
I really like the filling.
And you cut it in half, and you
get this wonderful smell.
MAN:
Handmade every day,
and the guys who run the joint
are class acts.
What else do you do
in your part-time?
I'm a railroad conductor
for Mass Bay.
Like "I've Been Working
on the Railroad"?
on the R--" Punching tickets.
All my live-long day?
Yeah, basically.
I want you to go ahead.
Go ahead.
[ Laughs ]
Now he's in control,
'cause he's got
the conductor hat on.
If you don't eat that, you're
out at the next stop, bro.
All right.
Chew, chew.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: And this train just keeps
rolling through Flavortown.
Next up,
another Old Country shout-out.
Rosette.
It's pasta with cheese and ham.
It's got a nice, little
crusty area on top,
but then it's soft and delicate
underneath.
Rosette's outstanding.
What are we
gonna make next?
We're gonna make rosette --
little roses.
When they're cooked, they look
like little, cooked white roses.
Okay.
There's the dough
for the rosette.
So, the sheets have been
parcooked off a little bit.
I'm gonna add
the cooked prosciutto
and the Fontina cheese now.
You want to take one side,
and I'll take the other?
[ Both stammering ]
Hey.
Hey. How you doing?
[ Laughs ]
Ready?
Hey. Roll.
Are we rolling it tight?
Yeah, tight.
All right, Guy, let's move.
We're gonna bring the cutting
board in, cut them up,
place them in the pan.
We're gonna add cream.
Nutmeg?
What have you got here?
A little nutmeg,
a little black pepper.
This is gonna be awesome.
We're gonna cork it now with
a little piece of aluminum foil.
What temperature?
How long?
450.
40 minutes or so.
I don't know that I'm gonna
be able to eat all of it,
but I'll sure try.
Oh, my gosh, man.
This is crazy.
Mm.
What this is --
This is a ham-and-cheese
sandwich meets lasagna.
It's light but super flavorful,
not overly salty.
That is a "stick-to-your-ribs,
you are so happy
that your mom is making this
for you" kind of meal.
WOMAN:
The presentation alone,
I just want to jump right in
and eat.
It's simple,
and I think that that's what --
Simple but done right.
That's it.
Very lucky that Boston
has a place like Casa Razdora.
This place, at lunch,
I've heard the reputation --
line down the street.
But what about at night?
How is it?
At night, we shut down.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
Nobody told me this!
Saturdays
and Sundays off.
So, one day,
I'm gonna call you
and ask you to stay open
till 7:00.
Don't worry about it, bro.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
Up next, in Cincinnati, Ohio...
[ Laughs ]
...a Jamaican joint...
I heard the chicken
is ridiculous.
...where the spice
is definitely nice.
This is
the basting technique?
Yeah, mon.
I love it.
You know, people
get in the restaurant business
for all kinds of reasons.
For a lot of them,
well, it's a family connection,
for some, it's a life passion,
and for others,
well, they see an opportunity
and they just run with it.
I'm here in Cincinnati, Ohio,
right over by the university,
to check out a joint
where I hear the food is amazing
and it's got a story to match.
This is Island Frydays.
Brown stew chicken.
It's paradise.
It really is a little island
in the middle of Cincinnati
for Jamaican food.
Oxtail, ready.
This is authentic Jamaican food.
There's no doubt.
I don't feel. I don't think.
I know.
FIERI: All cranked out
by Jamaican-born,
self-trained chef Leo Morgan,
who's known in these parts
for more than just cooking.
I was the number-one
outside linebacker in the nation
out of junior college
coming to U.C.
I played
strong-side linebacker.
You played.
You got injured.
Yes.
How did you end up
in the restaurant?
I used to always cook
for my teammates.
Every Friday
was Island Frydays.
That's how we have the name
on the building.
I just said,
"You know what?
Let's just keep it
Island Frydays."
Which meant
swapping out the gridiron
for the griddle in '09.
Tackling people,
and now we're tackling chicken.
It's a different story,
you know?
Everybody's told me
about this chicken.
I mean, I heard
the chicken is ridiculous.
MAN: Oh, the jerk chicken
is the bomb.
That's what we say.
[ Laughs ]
Jerk chicken, ready.
So, what are we gonna start with
first, here?
Well, we're gonna wash
the chicken with vinegar.
Just distilled
white vinegar?
Yeah, mon, regular.
And now the water.
Basically, just getting off
the excess blood, you know?
But it's also adding
a hint of flavor.
Yes.
Okay.
And dry them off.
I don't want
too much water.
We're gonna add
all-purpose seasoning.
Just a regular season salt?
Yeah.
Not too salty.
We're gonna season
this chicken again?
Yeah.
Now we're gonna add
the jerk seasoning.
So, this looks like
the regular cast of characters
when I do my jerk.
And this right here?
Pimento seed --
What you guys call allspice.
Right, we call it allspice.
Comes from the pimento tree?
Yes, sir.
This is gonna be the base
of your seasoning.
Now we have
the Scotch bonnet pepper.
Habaneros.
Onions.
He's very graceful.
Green onions.
Ginger.
Garlic.
[ Laughs ]
It's like an offering
to the gods.
All right.
[ Laughs ]
Cinnamon.
Nutmeg.
Black pepper.
Thyme.
Then we're gonna pour
the soy sauce and vinegar in.
And then we're ready
for blending.
Taste it?
Yeah, mon.
You have to get a bigger spoon,
a deeper spoon, man. Come on.
[ Jamaican accent ]
A deeper spoon, mon.
Spice up your life, mon.
Yeah. Wow, mon.
Want some water?
[ Normal voice ]
Ah, no.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're gonna season
the chicken.
Okay.
And rub it in by hand?
Yes, sir.
You want to use it lightly,
'cause it's heavy, you know?
Yeah, yeah, it's spicy.
Delicious, though.
Right.
All right, so,
we let this go for a day,
and then we'll throw it
on the grill.
Yes, sir.
I spray it
with a Red Stripe.
All right.
This is
the basting technique?
Yeah, man.
I love it.
So, now we're gonna
pull this off?
All right.
Basically,
we're just gonna cut up.
Like butter.
Easy.
Yeah, with the rice and peas.
Some cabbage.
Some plantains.
Piece of chicken.
Some of the finishing sauce.
Same jerk rub, we just --
You know, we cook it down.
I like it, mon.
Appreciate it.
Mm. The wood flavor
makes all the difference.
It's the foundation of it.
Mm.
The rub isn't as hot...
Good.
...as when I tasted it
straight out of the mixer,
but it's really deep
in the chicken.
That 24 hours
really did a lot for it.
Get a little bit
of that allspice,
a little bit of sweet
from the plantain.
Yes, sir.
Mm.
That's a ton of flavor.
Mm!
This is outstanding.
The jerk-chicken platter.
Oh, it's amazing.
It has the spice to it,
and it has a sweetness to it.
Beautifully smoked,
got a nice coat on the outside.
Hits the spot for me.
I fell in love
with the cooking.
I got a little bit
of Caribbean in me,
so it's like a second home
compared
to the football field.
You play ball
at the University of Cincinnati?
Yes, sir. If it wasn't for Leo,
we wouldn't be this big.
Honestly.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Okay, I got to stick
around this place,
so when we come back...
We're gonna make
the escovitch snapper.
...an off-the-hook
Jamaican take
on seafood.
Killer.
FIERI: "Triple D" is parked
in Cincinnati, Ohio,
for some righteous Jamaican
at Island Frydays.
When I can't get a good
home-cooked meal from my mom,
I love to come here.
FIERI: That's because here,
ex-linebacker Leo Morgan's
making the hits he grew up with.
As long as Leo cooks it,
you become a fan of it.
Escovitch fish, ready.
Escovitch sauce
is a traditional sauce
that we use normally
on the fish,
which is made of natural herbs
and spices from Jamaica.
They cook it the way I like it.
It's unbelievable.
We're gonna make
the escovitch snapper.
Right now, we're gonna clean up
the fish, the red snapper.
But first, we're gonna
doctor him up, you know,
take off
all the unnecessary parts.
Just clean him up,
give him a better presentation.
And then you'll
just scale them out.
Good to go.
So, you'll lay a couple cuts
into him.
Yeah.
Your choice. You know,
you have your fish seasoning.
It's a nice
island-flavor fish seasoning.
Lotion him up.
What?
That's a new one.
I haven't heard this one yet.
When we're putting this on,
what are we doing?
We lotion up the fish.
And let it marinate,
and we'll make
the escovitch sauce?
Right.
Got it.
We're gonna do vinegar.
Scotch bonnet.
Onions.
Carrots.
Sweet peppers,
just for color and taste.
Pimentos.
[ Whistles ]
Then we're gonna finish that
with some more vinegar.
More vinegar?
And we're gonna
let that simmer down?
Yeah, come to a boil.
How long does that take?
About 10 minutes.
And then
once we cook the fish,
we're gonna dip the fish
in that?
Yes, sir.
Bye-bye, fish.
And how long
will that cook?
5 minutes.
Some yellow rice.
And calalu.
What is calalu?
Jamaican greens.
And plantains again.
Now we're just gonna dip it
on one side, not for too long.
And then we'll change him
and turn him on the other side.
And that's how you do it?
That's it.
And he's good to go.
I'll finish him off
with some garnish.
Crazy.
Outstanding.
The fish is super moist.
Not oily.
The skin is fantastic.
The vinegar is
just the right amount of acid.
And what's in
the yellow rice?
Mixed vegetables --
Scotch bonnet,
green onions, onions.
The calalu?
Same thing --
Scotch bonnet,
green onion, tomatoes.
Killer.
MAN:
Oh, the fish is wonderful.
You sweating?
Oh, yeah.
MAN: Yeah, mon!
You can't get no better
than that, you know?
It's all the love,
you know?
I just try to basically do
the best I can, you know?
This is not about money.
It's about basically pleasing
somebody's taste buds, you know?
You're an amazing cat, man.
Nice to hang with you.
Appreciate you, Guy.
Yeah, mon.
FIERI:
Up next, in Duluth, Minnesota...
Thailand, Duluth.
...a Far East-Midwest mash-up...
Look at you,
Chef Fusion.
...going way beyond
traditional Thai.
Got to come see
this girl.
You know, I'm just like you.
I'm out cruising around,
and all of a sudden,
I get this hankering for some,
I don't know, like,
Southeast Asian cuisine,
and, well, I just happen to be,
like, on the North Shore
of Lake Superior.
I mean, it could happen.
You know, I'm on Grand Avenue,
right here
in west Duluth, Minnesota,
just a couple blocks away
from the Wisconsin border,
and I found the joint
you got to check out.
This is Pak's Green Corner.
Summer roll.
Oh, I just -- I love Pak's food.
MAN:
We came here the day she opened,
and we've been coming back
ever since.
All right, hi, folks.
How's it going?
There's a little bit of Pak
in every dish.
She's a saucy
little number.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Pak is short for --
get this --
Kamolpak Supa-Oath Williams,
who left Thailand,
settled in Minnesota,
and opened her roadside namesake
in 2012.
Thailand, Duluth.
Yeah.
I want to find
a new opportunity,
and I fall in love
with Lake Superior.
And the feeling's mutual.
These locals are loving
Pak's authentic Thai
and her culinary twists.
Pad Thai burrito.
Oh, the pad Thai burrito
is my favorite.
I get that almost every time
I come in here.
What dish
are we gonna make?
Pad Thai burrito.
Look at you,
Chef Fusion.
[ Laughs ]
What are we
gonna make first?
We do peanut sauce.
Start from oil.
Curry paste.
And this is sugar.
Then we stir it
together,
and after that,
we add coconut milk.
Vinegar?
Yep.
And a little salt?
And then peanut butter
and ground peanut.
And that's the peanut sauce.
Yeah, peanut sauce.
Okay.
All right.
Now we do pad Thai
burrito mix.
We start with oil.
Now eggs.
And then chicken, carrot,
cabbage, fresh garlic,
and salted daikon.
Okay.
Rice noodles.
Then we add water.
And then pad Thai sauce.
A little bit ketchup
for the color.
A little bit paprika.
And then stir-fry sauce.
Stir-fry sauce.
Scallion.
When it's ready.
we add this.
And then put the pad Thai.
Peanut sauce.
Cayenne pepper.
Okay.
And we roll it.
All right.
Nice job.
Mm-hmm.
That's delicious
pad Thai.
The fact that you could put it
into a burrito,
into something
that I can eat portable,
is genius.
Just the way you rolled it,
just the way you make it
so inviting -- excellent.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
That peanut sauce
is to die for.
The flavor
just snaps in your mouth.
WOMAN:
I get cravings for it.
Like, "Oh, I have to go
eat that."
There's a lot of Asian food,
so what's the difference?
How do you
explain Thai food?
Thai food is more light,
and the sauce --
It's not too thick
like Chinese...
Right.
...and not too greasy.
FIERI: And don't forget
about curry...
Lamb karee curry
for you, Jim.
FIERI: ...another Thai staple
Pak's got covered.
It's a lot more intense
than a lot of other foods.
The lamb karee curry
is the best.
Okay, what are we
gonna make next?
Lamb karee curry.
Okay.
This is the lamb
that I already cleaned.
Okay.
So, we're gonna cut
in a small piece.
Okay.
And then we will marinate
with coffee.
To cut down on the gaminess.
Yeah.
And we wrap it.
How long are we gonna
let this marinate?
Overnight.
So, the lamb marinated
in the coffee.
Yeah.
Now we're gonna sear
the lamb.
Paper towel, please.
Oh, it's a nice stand.
[ Laughter ]
My new job.
All right.
Smell good.
So, now we let these sear
on both sides?
Yep.
Now we're gonna put it
in here?
Right.
Bay leaf.
And the peppercorns?
Yep.
Tricolor.
Water.
And 3 hours.
3 to 4 hours.
Until it's really tender.
Yeah.
And while this is going,
we're gonna make the curry?
Yeah.
Here's the oil,
and then curry paste.
Who made the curry?
I make.
What's in the curry?
Lemongrass, dry chili peppers,
cumin, and paprika.
And then boiled potato.
Boiled carrot.
Zucchini.
Then whipping cream.
So, heavy cream.
And then the rib.
Okay.
And stir-fry sauce.
Stir-fry sauce.
So, we will cook
a little bit.
Now rice -- basmati.
Basmati?
Yeah.
Then we will dash lemon,
and then cilantro.
Put the lamb.
Look at how pretty
that is.
And then we top it
with sour cream,
and ready to go.
It's a really nice dish.
I like the curry.
I've had
a lot of Thai dishes.
This has a very strong
Indian flavor to it.
Yep.
I like the lamb.
I like that coffee flavor.
This shows the diversity
of the type of food
that you have in Thailand.
Delicious.
WOMAN: You feel like royalty
eating lamb with that.
It's just fabulous.
The lamb is tender.
It's just nice and succulent.
MAN: This restaurant
is a labor of love.
Pak is a person who truly cares
about her customers.
WOMAN: Besides the fact
that she's a fabulous cook,
she's just the most
gracious hostess.
Hello!
This is great.
This is the American dream.
Tiny, little place
right here on a fast road
going into Duluth.
I don't think people expect
when they pull in
they're gonna find food
with such broad profile
of flavor.
You're awesome.
Got to come see
this girl.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Laughter ]
Look at the mess
we made, bro.
Wait a second.
This is where
I've been eating.
Ah, come on.
Wait a second.
This is where I've been eating.
What's going on over here,
Bobby?
I'm sorry, bro.
[ Laughter ]