Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Yeah!
...we're filling up
on some serious sauces.
Send me home
with a gallon of that.
In Jackson, Wyoming...
Whoa!
Going for the gusto.
...a century-old
down-home joint...
Nothing I don't like
about that.
...turning out
righteous new ways
to pile on the pork.
This is pig-on-pig.
In Cincinnati, Ohio,
a traditional topper...
We usually make
like 32 quarts a day or more.
This is a soup kitchen?
...made with
an untraditional twist.
♪ Get down with TVP
Yeah, you know me ♪
And in
Boston, Massachusetts...
Don't buy one beer
when you have this.
Buy like 10.
...a sandwich shop...
Pita pocket.
...where the sauce
is the boss.
My job is over!
Thank you. Very nice.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here on East Broadway
in Jackson, Wyoming,
about a half block away
from the town square.
Now, there's a lot of history
and a lot of characters
in this town,
and the next joint
we're gonna visit has both.
We're talking about
a super-eclectic menu
served out of
a 104-year-old log cabin.
This is Café Genevieve.
The food's fantastic.
It's out of this world.
Fried chicken.
Kind of feels like
you're in someone's dining room.
FIERI:
No wonder it feels like home.
It's actually a cabin
built in 1910,
and 100 years later,
Fred and Daryl Peightal
and Josh Governale
turned it into a restaurant.
You named it Café Genevieve
in tribute to the lady
that lived
in the house first.
She was on the first
all-women's town council.
This place was kind of
a meeting place.
And they're making sure
it stays that way.
We have people from all over
the world that come here,
so this menu is really varied,
from the traditional
New York City-style Reuben
to an Asian ramen.
Ramen? Come on.
It is absolutely amazing.
WOMAN:
Ramen noodle bowl.
This is one of a kind here,
and it's awesome.
We're going into
our pork ramen dish,
and there's two types of meat --
pork belly, pork butt.
FIERI: Fantastic.
First we're gonna start
with the rub.
Some apples,
garlic, ginger.
Jalapeños.
A little apple juice.
[ Whistles ]
Limes.
Oh. Going for the gusto.
Salt, pepper.
This is gonna be
a heck of a marinade.
Ooh.
That's right.
Nothing I don't like
about that.
We're gonna let it marinate
for five hours.
We're gonna roast it
in the oven
at 375 degrees
for 2½ hours.
Now we're gonna start
to braise.
First thing is onions,
jalapeños.
More ginger.
Limes, garlic.
Okay.
Put the pork on top.
Apple juice,
chicken stock.
Now, this gets covered?
Wrap it up.
How long we gonna go?
225 degrees for four hours.
[ Click ]
Haunted.
It's the ghost
of Genevieve.
I knew
you were gonna say that.
So, we're gonna make
our ramen noodles.
Right now,
we have baking soda
that's been baked
in the oven.
Makes it into
an alkaline salt.
Doesn't look
any different.
Nope.
But the chemical transformation
has taken place.
Exactly.
I love it.
This is your tablespoon
measuring system?
Yes, sir.
Awesome. My style.
2 tablespoons of that.
Warm water to dissolve it.
Cold water.
And we're gonna incorporate
the flour.
And that's gonna mix
for five minutes.
[ Click ]
Genevieve.
She's here.
How long you let it rest?
20 minutes.
So, we'll roll this out
to number five.
And we're gonna cut this
with an almost angel-hair --
Oh! That's awesome.
That is thin.
This is ready?
Yep.
GOVERNALE: We got our
pork shoulder that came out.
FIERI: Okay.
Pork belly.
This is pig on pig.
Look at that.
Thick slice.
This is gonna go
on the flattop.
Pulled pork.
All right, now I'm gonna drop
the noodles in the water.
It's like real-deal ramen
right there, man.
Pork belly.
The other side of the bowl
is gonna be the pork shoulder.
Fresh basil, cilantro,
fresh mint,
little pickled daikon.
Ramen broth.
This guy in the middle.
It is pha-nomenal.
It's outrageous, brah.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Mmm.
The fact that you go through
all this time and energy
to make every aspect
of the dish.
You got salty, you got sweet.
It is just so well done.
Mmm. You can tell
I don't like this.
[ Chuckles ]
It's really delicious.
WOMAN:
Love the pork belly in it.
So to be able
to throw it into a ramen bowl
like this is really nice.
I love pig. We love pig.
I love pig, yeah.
FIERI: But it looks like
my love's about to be tested...
Pork neck.
Pork neck?
Yeah.
I always enjoy
a good pork neck.
...when we come back.
FIERI:
All right, so here we are.
We're back
in Jackson Hole, Wyoming,
and we are hanging out
at Café Genevieve.
We just got done
having the bomb ramen.
Now we are onto
pork necks.
This looks not that --
That does -- No, not good.
Not appetizing?
Not so much.
Well,
it's gonna be appetizing.
We rub it
and make it into a ragout.
So, we got black pepper,
kosher salt,
smoked paprika,
ground fennel.
Ooh.
Garlic powder,
mustard powder.
Chili powder.
Chili powder, dried thyme.
Now we're gonna roast them
at 325 for two hours.
So, the necks are back.
Yep,
and now we're gonna braise them.
So, what we're gonna do
is we do mirepoix
on the bottom again.
Onions, carrots,
roasted romas, whole garlic,
pork neck bones
go right in.
Fresh thyme.
Thyme sprigs.
And...
Chicken stock.
Now what temp, how long?
225...
overnight.
Seriously?
Yeah. Slow and low.
Why so long?
The gelatinous
that comes off that pork neck
is incredible.
Now we've pulled
all the meat.
We're now
gonna build this.
Yes.
What is our sauce here?
That is the braising liquid
pureed, strained.
Fantastic.
And here we go.
Olive oil.
Start with the pancetta.
You want to render that down.
And you add
the carrots and the onions.
This is really gonna cook down
to nothing.
Yeah. Gonna tighten up.
Okay.
Sweat that down, add your garlic
towards the end
because you don't want to
burn it.
Lots of garlic, too.
Add your pulled pork.
This is all
that pulled neck meat,
all that deep,
rich pork flavor.
So, this is some white wine,
to deglaze it.
I'm gonna let that
come down.
And then we're hitting it
with this fantastic, rich stock.
Yeah.
Cook this down.
Finish it with a little thyme,
fresh thyme, chopped up.
And a little parsley.
Parsley.
How long's
this gonna cook down?
About 45 minutes
to an hour.
What are we serving
this with?
Homemade
pappardelle pasta.
Do you buy anything?
Medium-high sauté pan.
Okay.
Butter.
Look at this.
Send me home
with a gallon of that.
Oh!
Fresh thyme.
Parsley.
Let those noodles finish
in that ragout.
A little fresh ricotta
that we make here.
Of course you do.
Throw that
in the salamander.
Finish with
a little breadcrumbs.
Here we go.
Here we are.
Home-cooked food.
Tender, flavorful,
deep, balanced, all of it.
Are there Italian restaurants
in this town?
Two?
This is not fair to them.
You're not supposed to come in
and do this.
It's like playing
all the sports.
Well,
your restaurant
is like the Bo Jackson
of restaurants.
Making your noodles,
making your pasta,
cooking down
the pork necks.
I mean, you rocked it.
Oh, that's good!
Pork neck ragout.
All right. Thank you.
Just a really good dish.
And the pork
is just out of this world.
The pasta's cooked perfectly.
It's so full of flavor.
It's my buddy Johnny
from California.
Johnny and I
were flambé captains together
at the Red Lion
Motor Inn.
What do you think?
Delicious, great place,
great food.
It's just part of what you do
when you come to Jackson.
FIERI: This is awesome.
People come for the skiing,
come for the wilderness,
come back for this joint.
Coming up
in Boston, Massachusetts...
That is over the top.
...a spot hitting the sauce...
Dare I say "Flavortown"?
Brother,
this drove through Flavortown.
...and jazzing up the Joe.
Was that jazz hands flair
you just gave me?
These are jazz hands, yeah.
So, I'm here in Boston
in one of the busiest
tourist areas in the city.
I'm right by the aquarium,
Faneuil Hall, and Haymarket.
Now, there are so many places
to eat,
but I hear a joint you got to
check out is right here at Saus.
Crispy chicken.
You can't go wrong with
pretty much anything you order.
The Sloppy Jacques.
Been here before?
About 20, 50 times.
This week?
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: And the guy
keeping them coming back
is co-owner and chef Chin Kuo,
who opened this joint with some
college buddies back in 2011.
So, why is it called Saus?
It's "sauce" in Dutch.
Inspired by
Dutch Greek food.
We're all about
the condiments.
Yep, all 20 of them,
ranging from savory to sweet.
All of the sauces are amazing.
What dipping sauces
do you enjoy?
I like Samurai,
I like Vampire Slayer.
Sounds like a comic book.
[ Laughs ]
You can use
a lot of the different sauces
on all of the sandwiches.
KUO: Chicken saté pocket up.
I really love
the chicken pocket.
MAN: You got some crunch,
and there are some carrots
and some onions
and some chicken.
It all comes together
in a really great bite.
What are we gonna make
today?
The Lemongrass Chicken
Saté pocket.
Okay.
Here we have boneless skinless
chicken thighs.
Next up?
We're gonna make
the marinade.
Regular granulated sugar,
dark soy sauce,
garlic powder,
lot of lemongrass,
and then we also have
some ground ginger.
And I'm just gonna go ahead
and mix it up.
How long will this marinate?
For a day?
Exactly.
And then how are we
gonna prepare it to serve?
I'm gonna deep-dry it.
To go into the pocket?
That's right.
And it's a pocket of what?
Pita pocket.
Pita pocket!
So, here we're gonna make
the pindasaus.
The pindasaus?
Yes.
It translates
to "peanut sauce" in Dutch.
Got it.
It starts with just
regular creamy peanut butter.
Okay.
Next, we're gonna add
the saté sauce.
It's a very savory mix
of goodness.
Some dark soy sauce,
chili paste,
little bit of lemon juice,
sesame oil,
garlic powder,
and ginger powder.
Just gonna add
a little bit of water.
And you're gonna hit this
with an immersion blender?
That's correct.
Gonna add some greens,
fresh chopped onions,
parsley vinaigrette.
I'm gonna add this chicken
that's out of the fryer.
So, we're just
gonna slice this pita bread
down the middle here.
Add this peanut sauce.
Gonna add the chicken
and the greens, the vinaigrette,
and then just gonna drizzle
a little bit
more peanut sauce on top.
And that's all she wrote.
Great sandwich, man.
Peanut sauce
isn't overdone with peanut.
Chicken's nice and tender
and crunchy.
Outrageous texture.
Nice, big, hearty sandwich,
lot of flavors.
Very good.
Nice job, man.
Thanks very much.
KUO:
Chicken saté pocket up.
The pindasaus
has Asian-style flavors --
salty but a little sweet.
Do you have
a culinary background?
I do not.
[ Laughs ] Okay.
This is what happened.
We moved off campus,
so I had to start cooking,
and there was
the Food Network.
I'm done!
That's a secret.
My job is over!
Thank you. Very nice.
All the food
is really great here.
They got little bites,
they've got, you know,
big meals.
Sloppy Jacques,
here we go!
The Sloppy Jacques
is one of those sandwiches
that just kind of remind you
of childhood.
It's braised beef and bacon
served on a brioche bun.
Why is it called
"Jacques"?
I guess you can say
it's the sloppy Joe
with some flair,
some Jacques.
Was that jazz hands flair
you just gave me?
These are jazz hands,
yeah.
Shhhh!
Yeah, there we go.
First thing
we're gonna start with.
Applewood-smoked bacon
and also pork belly scraps.
So, I'm just gonna take this
and give it a good stir
and render down
the fat.
Onions.
All right,
next up we have the ground beef.
Okay.
I'll spot you, okay?
Help me out.
Here you go.
So, ground beef's cooked,
onions are sweated.
Next up we have
just a cornstarch slurry.
House-made ketchup,
Worcestershire,
Dijon mustard,
lots of salt
and lots of black pepper.
Last thing we're gonna add --
milk stout.
It's gonna add some --
A nice, big, deep,
rich stout.
And how long
we gonna let this cook down?
You know,
15, 20 minutes or so.
All right, so I'm gonna plate
the Sloppy Jacques now.
First I'm gonna start
with a brioche roll,
some of this ketchup,
cheddar cheese,
quite a lot of this
right on top.
Hey-o!
Little bit
of pickled red onion.
That's for you.
Really rich.
That is big flavor.
If you like the sloppy Joes,
that is over the top.
[ Chuckles ]
You're getting the beer,
you definitely get
the seasoning.
It's really got a sweet note
that's coming
from the house-made ketchup,
I think.
Don't buy one beer
when you have this.
Buy like 10.
I love the savory,
sweet kind of balance
of the bacon and the stout.
It's a little bit of a mess
to eat, but a glorious mess.
This guy right here,
Samuel Monsour,
won one of the first challenges
in "Guy's Grocery Games,"
"Triple G."
He's a fantastic chef.
Tell me about
the Sloppy Jacques.
Big flavors, huge portion.
I love it.
All the food at Saus
is fresh.
You get some of the locals.
You get some of the tourists.
Great people-watching
and a lot of fun every time.
You have pushed the boundary
of sloppy Joes.
Dare I say "Flavortown"?
Brother,
this drove through Flavortown.
[ Chuckles ]
Nice job.
All right. Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
Here we go.
In Cincinnati, Ohio,
a funky, fresh place
cooking up the classics...
"Legit" legit.
...with their own
signature spin.
You're not only pulling it off.
You're rocking the house.
So, I'm here
at Cincinnati, Ohio,
on Hamilton Avenue,
about five miles from downtown
right over by the colleges.
Now, when I say Cincinnati,
what do you think?
Well, you definitely think
the Cincinnati Reds,
but you got to think about
the chili,
'cause here
they do chilis three-way,
they do chili four ways,
and five-way.
But I'm here
to check out a joint
that's doing chili their way.
That's right --
vegetarian chili.
This is Melt.
Vegan penne.
MAN: They say
this is a vegetarian place,
but I'm a meat eater,
and I love it.
Vegan cheesesteak
with garden bash.
Very unique, but it fits
the neighborhood perfectly.
FIERI:
And keeping the vibe alive,
owner and chef Lisa Kagen.
So, I just wanted this
to be a place
where the vegetarian
girlfriend could eat
with the guy that wanted
the slow-braised beef.
FIERI: And since '05,
Lisa's been putting her spin
on a Cincinnati tradition
that matches up spaghetti,
chili, and cheese.
Vegetarian 3-way.
It looks like
a regular Cincinnati 3-way.
I was really surprised
to learn that it was vegetarian.
FIERI: Here we go.
KAGEN: So, I'm gonna start
with some oil
and some minced garlic.
Diced onions,
diced peppers,
green bell pepper.
And then we're gonna add
the chili seasonings.
So, we've got cinnamon,
oregano,
paprika,
cayenne,
garlic salt,
chili powder,
allspice,
black pepper,
brown sugar.
We're going to just splash
a little red-wine vinegar
in there.
Kchhh!
Get that going.
We usually make
like 32 quarts a day or more.
This a soup kitchen?
So, instead of ground beef,
we use the TVP --
texturized
vegetable protein.
♪ Get down with TVP
Yeah, you know me ♪
[ Laughs ]
Tomato filets.
And the cooked black beans.
And some vegetable stock.
How long
we gonna let this cook?
No longer than an hour.
It cooks up pretty fast.
Our whole wheat noodles.
Holy moly.
And we sprinkle
with white cheddar.
Red onion.
I like sriracha.
May I?
Oh, yeah.
All right. Here we go.
I don't think
anybody could tell you
there's not meat in that.
[ Chuckles ] Thank you.
Yeah, I like it
because it's real chili.
You can see
what you're eating.
It's not a bunch
of pureed-out meat sauce.
The beans are tender.
The TVP is perfect in there.
You're not only pulling it off.
You're rocking the house.
Thank you.
Great job.
[ Laughs ]
KAGEN: Vegetarian 3-way.
The chili, it's like I used to
get over at my grandma's house.
It's so rich and hearty.
It's got so much flavor to it.
So, if you come
to Cincinnati,
you got to go to a Reds game,
and you got to try chili.
I've got a buddy of mine
who plays ball for the Reds,
number 48,
outfielder Ryan Ludwick.
Ryan, you think
if we took this to the clubhouse
and let some of the guys
try it?
I think
if this was in the clubhouse,
you'd find nothing left
on this plate
when the guys
were done with it.
When you love what you do,
it shows in your food.
I guess
you get a little love.
What pushed you
to open your own joint?
So, there was nowhere really
to go to get food
that was free of food coloring,
preservatives,
high fructose corn syrup.
You focus on all of our meats
being clean as possible.
Good energy!
Yes.
Yeehaw chicken.
MAN: I've got the Yeehaw
barbecue sandwich.
Stuff's really good.
Okay,
what are we gonna do next?
The Yeehaw barbecue.
[ Laughs ]
You can't name something
the Yeehaw without giving a --
We have
the Yeehaw barbecue!
Yeah!
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
We're about to prep the chicken.
Pepper.
Kosher salt,
onion powder,
garlic powder.
Sprinkle that
over the chicken.
We're gonna add
the sherry and oil
and just add a little bit
of water to cover it.
And this will get popped in
the oven at what temp, how long?
350 for about 25 minutes.
Now we're making
the barbecue sauce?
Yes.
We are gonna start off with
our house-made ketchup base.
We're going to add
the molasses
and some minced
pickled jalapeños,
hot sauce,
little bit
more brown sugar here,
allspice,
canned chipotle
in adobo sauce,
extra strong Dijon,
and some corn starch.
We're just gonna blend
everything into the ketchup.
All right.
I just let that cool.
Let's build the sandwich.
We're going to
split the hoagie in half
and add the chicken.
Pico on this side.
Lay some tomatoes.
Barbecue sauce.
Lay the smoked mozzarella
on top.
Into the oven?
Takes about three minutes,
500.
Here we go.
So, we have...
Ta-da.
That's a lot more
than a barbecue sandwich.
The pico is the key.
That's what takes it
the next step.
The barbecue sauce
is "legit" legit.
Chicken's got
its own great flavor.
That's a dangerous balance.
[ Laughs ]
Outstanding.
Thank you. [ Laughs ]
Barbecue sauce is excellent.
It's sweet, it's tangy.
It's also got a really good
smoky mozzarella cheese on it.
FIERI: So, if you think
about Cincinnati,
there's a restaurant
you definitely know about,
and that's Jeff Ruby's.
That's his daughter
right here.
This is
Britney Ruby Miller.
How does this kind
of a vegetarian-type restaurant
fit in Cincinnati?
MILLER: She's been able to take
all the flavors
and keep it true
to Cincinnati
but still make it clean,
healthy, and tons of flavor.
MAN: When I have people visit
from out of town,
this is one of the first places
that they want to come to.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Shut the back door.
I will.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
MAN: He shut it.