Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Don't be a-scared.
...we're going
from Jersey to Cali...
And he's running.
...getting our
East Coast, West Coast fix.
It's addicting.
First in
Bakersfield, California...
Got to have
a little wango tango.
...an iconic,
down-home steakhouse...
This is about as old-school
as it gets.
...where the character's kicking
his way through the kitchen.
Dude's taking over
the show.
And across town...
Oh, yes!
...a funky
Latin experience...
Cha-cha-cha?
...putting fancy footwork
into fusion.
Now you're getting
the rumba.
Then in Somers Point,
New Jersey...
What up?
...a standout
sandwich shop...
The only thing you need
when you come into to get that
is a friend
to drive you home...
...delivering
a knockout combo.
...and
a medical release.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here in south New Jersey
in a town called Somers Point.
Now, this is
where people cruise through
to go down to the boardwalk
and Ocean City.
But more importantly,
to visit this joint.
This is The Grilled Cheese
& Crab Cake Company.
♪ Down to Somers Point ♪
♪ To a funky little joint
called The Crab Cake Co ♪
It's a catchy name.
Everything is amazing.
Big Bad Fishwich.
Everybody comes in here
and is like,
"Oh, what do you guys serve
here?"
Grilled cheese and crab cakes.
FIERI: And the guy marrying
the two is Steve Novak...
Throw on another crab cake
for the other melt now.
...who bought this place
back in 2010
thanks to a little help
from the family --
brothers pitching in and
grandparents backing them up.
Got to love Grandma.
But Grandma,
she dropped the coin.
Grandma Tarantine.
We call her "G-Tar,"
though.
What up?
And Grandma's investment
is built on a classic.
Who doesn't love grilled cheese?
It's the ultimate comfort food.
WOMAN: You can put anything
inside a grilled cheese,
and he does it the best.
I got the crab melt.
WOMAN:
It's a grilled cheese sandwich,
and it has a crab cake
in the middle.
It's what
they're known for here.
Let's get into it.
All right, so,
the first thing we're gonna do
is add our mayo to the bin.
Next, we're gonna add
our eggs.
Then our fresh lemon juice.
I like to use
honey mustard.
A little Sriracha --
I think Sriracha
just makes everything better.
Just a little Crystal Hot Sauce,
a little extra heat.
And then
Worcestershire sauce.
Wor-shur-shur sauce.
Old Bay seasoning.
Say "hey" for Old Bay.
There you go.
Your black pepper?
Hey-y-y-y-y.
Actually,
this is celery seed...
[ Both laugh ]
He's at one point
over here.
A little celery seed.
Very nice.
And then baking powder.
A load of
fresh-chopped parsley.
And then
we whisk her up.
She's good to go.
Next, we add
our panko bread crumbs.
So, you want to make sure
it's incorporated in real good.
Now the crab.
Let's talk about that.
Jumbo lump.
Treat it very gingerly now,
correct?
Exactly.
'Cause you don't want
to bust it up.
People like to see
those real big lumps.
My lovely,
crabby lumps.
That is some creamy...
Actually, this will solidify
once it sets.
It's gonna have to.
So, we're gonna throw
a little butter on the grill.
We're gonna take
our crab cake,
put it right on the butter,
butter the bread.
You and butter.
Monterey Jack cheese.
Shouldn't you have it
on a squirt pump or something?
[ Laughs ]
Probably.
We're gonna
steam the bread
just to make sure
we melt the cheese real good.
So, we're gonna let this cook up
on both sides?
This is our crab melt.
Whew. Wow.
Crab cake
is a little bit creamier
than what
most people expect.
Crispy on the outside,
tons of crab.
No question about
the amount of crab in there.
Nice crunch of the toast,
not too much cheese.
You pull it off, man.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
I love it. [ Laughs ]
It's a favorite.
It's moist, it's fresh,
it's delicious.
You can either have it
plain or angry.
"Angry" here means
Sriracha and jalapeños.
You make the cheesesteaks angry.
Cream of crab soup --
you can get that angry.
Having the sandwich angry
makes me very happy.
FIERI: And another hit
making folks smile...
I love the pork belly Reuben.
Pork belly Reuben up.
It's one of the most epic
sandwiches on the menu.
We're doing pork belly
here.
We just have
a real simple rub.
We're gonna start
with a little kosher salt.
A little black pepper.
Garlic powder.
Rosemary.
A little bit of oil...
Just so it sticks.
...so it's pasty.
Mix her in.
How about we do this?
Yeah, that works.
So, we give it a rub,
and we leave it
for about 24 hours.
And we're gonna
put it in our roasting pan
and roast it
for three hours.
Word to the pig.
All right, we're making
Grandma G-Tar's sauerkraut.
We're gonna mix up the brine --
apple cider vinegar.
We got our apple cider.
Kosher salt.
Crushed caraways.
Very nice.
We add our cabbage
to the brine.
Back into
the microwave-safe container.
I feel like this is probably
a one-person job.
If you wait out back,
that'd be great.
Good luck with that.
[ Laughs ]
All right, I'm ready.
Do you need me?
Okay, I'm back.
All right. Great.
Gosh, you were able to do that
all by yourself?
Grandma bought me
a restaurant
'cause I could put stuff
in bowls all by myself.
"Put stuff in bowls"!
We cover this bad boy up.
This is gonna go for
about five minutes.
Pork belly.
I like to slice the pieces
pretty thick.
Like buttah.
It's a sandwich.
That's a sandwich?
Take our four slices,
nice hot pan.
A little marble rye.
We got to butter that.
Oh-ho-ho!
We're gonna add
a little Swiss.
Now we cover it,
melt that cheese,
and throw on our kraut.
Top it with sauerkraut.
We add our pork belly.
Hit it with our homemade
Russian dressing.
It's about the most ridiculously
huge sandwich
I've seen in a while.
That's
our pork belly Reuben.
Mmm.
Brother,
I am telling you what.
This has got
a lot of texture to it.
It's got a lot of flavor.
The pork belly's dynamite.
You toasted the bread nice,
even though it's got
tons of moisture around it.
You did it.
You nailed this one.
Mmm.
The only thing you need
when you come in to get that
is a friend to drive you home
and a medical release.
[ Laughs ]
Crazy delicious.
I love everything about it.
He kills it
with the pork.
You're, like, giving it
mouth-to-mouth right now.
You're saving this thing.
Working on it.
We need food like this.
WOMAN: He's making a good name
for himself
and for Somers Point, too.
You love food, you dig people,
you're into this.
Nicely done,
brother.
Thanks.
FIERI: Up next,
in Bakersfield, California...
What a place!
...a real-deal,
throwback steakhouse...
Hanging out with characters
of all characters.
...hitting the mark
for over 75 years.
If it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
So, I'm here
in Bakersfield, California,
about two hours north
of Los Angeles.
Now, what do you find here?
You got it --
oil and agriculture.
Now, you're gonna
have to look pretty hard
to find a sushi restaurant.
But you don't have to look
too hard to find this joint.
This is KC Steakhouse.
Top sirloin, medium rare.
This is
what a steakhouse should be.
The best steaks in the world.
It's an icon in Bakersfield.
FIERI:
That's because it's been a town
staple for over seven decades.
Well, this place has
a lot of character.
I think that's the best way
to describe it.
FIERI:
Which is one of the things
employees Missy Pelton
and her daughter Cassie Bittle
loved about it.
But in 2010, the game changed
when a new buyer
started sniffing around.
They kind of wanted to clean
house and redo it their way.
Why did you buy it?
So everybody
would keep their jobs
and that
this wouldn't change.
We stayed a family.
FIERI: People tell stories about
they came here as a kid
and then
they brought their kids,
and their kids brought their
kids, and it goes on and on.
That's Chef Forrest O'Sullivan's
story, too.
I remember my parents
taking me to dinner here.
I could stand up
in the booth
to look at the people
next to me.
I did that right here
in the KC Steakhouse.
A lot of old-school specialties
on the menu --
like,
stuff you can't mess with.
No.
This is the way
we've been doing it.
Yeah, this is the way
This is the way
it's gonna stay.
MAN:
This is not nouveau cuisine,
where you have
like three peas on a plate.
FIERI: Not even close.
Instead, they're loading up on
good old down-home favorites.
You normally wouldn't order
mac and cheese
in a steakhouse, would you?
FIERI: Unless, of course,
there's lobster in it.
I personally wouldn't
have thought
that lobster goes with
mac and cheese, but it does.
It's wonderful.
Lobster mac and cheese.
Mac and cheese.
What makes good mac and cheese,
in your world?
Cheese.
[ Laughs ]
Well,
there you have it.
I mean, I'm the one
asking the dumb questions.
All right, let's start
making some lobster.
We have
North Atlantic lobster tail.
Crack him.
How are we gonna make
this lobster?
We're gonna steam it
in the oven.
Water.
Pickling spice.
Interesting.
It makes it
real aromatic.
I like it.
Paprika for color.
Okay, so,
now we go to the oven.
And this goes fast.
Sure.
Bring it out,
let it cool.
You chop it up?
And then we'll start to make
the mac and cheese.
And then we'll make
some macaroni and cheese.
We start with
some heavy cream.
Okay.
Cheddar cheese.
Got to have a good,
old-fashioned American cheese.
Oh, you got to have
some of that in there.
Ain't mac and cheese
without the American.
'Merican, yeah.
[ Laughs ]
'Merican.
A little blue cheese.
You got to have
a little wango tango.
Garlic.
Chopped onions.
Coarse black pepper.
Kosher salt.
And a little cavatappi mac.
This is the lobster.
Everybody in the pool.
That's the size portion
we're giving them?
Uh-huh. That's it.
Holy moly!
To-go boxes are big
at the KC.
I just want
to come and see him.
[ Laughs ]
So, I'll let it rock 'n' roll
for a few minutes.
Rock 'n' roll.
All that's gonna go
in there?
It's like putting
your skinny jeans on, huh?
Nobody here
has skinny jeans.
Now we're gonna do
a little Parmesan cheese.
And a little
Japanese bread crumbs.
Parsley.
And a little blowtorch
for color.
He knows
no boundaries.
Good, old-school
garlic bread there.
That is
the lobster mac and cheese.
The key is,
is when you bite into it,
you should really get
big chunks of lobster.
It's creamy.
I like the blue cheese mix, too.
Uh-huh. It works.
Big pieces of lobster.
Loved the little crunch you did
from the panko.
The pasta is nice and tender.
It's not overcooked.
You really hit it. Not everybody
can do mac and cheese.
You got to have
that big kid in you.
The big kid at the KC --
The Forrest.
That's dynamite, man.
Nice job.
You like mac and cheese,
you're gonna love this.
The noodles are great. They
hold the cheese really well.
You have to stick to some of
the basic, simple ingredients,
and I think
they do that here.
So, this is one
of my really close friends.
This is Michael Osterman.
How does this restaurant
stay here for 76 years?
I think the biggest part
is they treat everybody
like family when they walk in.
They have loyal guests
that come back,
and the next generation
comes with them.
It's just really a neighborhood
place where people congregate.
Me and a couple of my friends
here,
we should probably
own the place.
We've spent
enough money here.
It's what you would find at a
steakhouse in the '60s and '70s
when you got
what you paid for.
Stuffed pork chop
with the cranberry relish.
What else
you gonna make me?
Oh, we're gonna go with
the stuffed pork chop.
The Forrest show at the KC
with the guy from the "Triple D"
when we come back,
hanging out in Bakersfield.
See you in a minute.
I'm the Forrest.
This is the KC with "Triple D."
Dude's taking over
the show.
We're in Bakersfield
hanging out with characters
of all characters,
and we're at a joint
called KC Steakhouse.
But as Forrest refers to it,
it's "The KC."
So, we just did
lobster mac and cheese --
the bomb.
And now we're making
one of your specialties.
A stuffed pork chop
with a cranberry relish.
[ Giggles ]
[ Laughs ]
Did you see him
just get a little
internal giggle right there?
Like...
[ Giggles ]
All right,
let's get after it.
We're gonna make
the stuffing first.
First ingredient --
drawn butter.
Chopped onions.
Okay.
Chopped celery.
Chopped garlic.
You gonna put
all that salt in there?
Nah, nah. Don't worry.
I ain't gonna hurt you.
Don't be a-scared.
Black pepper.
And we need some apples.
All that's gonna go
in one pork chop?
Mm, most of it.
How big of a pork chop
is this?
14 to 16.
14 to 16 what?
Ounces.
We're gonna sauté this
a little bit.
Getting hot.
[ Laughs ]
Well done, Chef.
There we go.
There you go.
Now you got it. You got it.
All right, now.
Next, I'm gonna add
some cream cheese.
Mix this up nice and good.
We're gonna add
good, old-fashioned
sourdough bread crumbs.
Chopped fresh sage.
You go, buddy.
Okay, now we're gonna make
the cranberry relish
that's gonna go
on top.
Goes on top
of the pork chop.
Water.
Sugar.
Got it.
Cranberries.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Cayenne pepper.
Chopped garlic.
Diced red pepper.
And chopped onions.
All right. So, how long
does this cook down for?
Oh, about 12 minutes.
12 minutes says the Forrest
at the KC.
At the KC.
All right.
With the Guy.
And with the Guy.
Here with the Guy.
See?
He couldn't let me do it.
He's going after my job.
No, no.
Bone-in pork chop.
Okay.
And we are going to
stuff him.
We're gonna cut a hole
in him.
Here's the stuffing.
We're gonna stuff him
real good.
We got a little
Montreal steak seasoning.
Throw it on the broiler.
And that's it?
And we're gonna let that roll
for how long?
10, 15 minutes.
And he's running.
Run, Forrest.
Run.
Vegetable medley --
lots of pepper,
lots of garlic.
Rice pilaf.
Stuffed pork chop.
Okay.
Cranberry relish.
All right, buddy.
And then here we are
with the super chop.
This is about as old-school
as it gets.
That's good, man.
What do you think of that?
That's good.
Great stuffing.
Thank you.
Love the celery.
Love that you grilled it.
The texture from the grill
is great --
the little bit
of the char you get.
Cranberry sauce is outstanding.
Doesn't overwhelm it.
Doesn't take the flavor
away from it.
And rice pilaf
and vegetable medley --
I mean, that's, like,
that's the KC's middle name.
This is the kind of food
that you expect.
But you know what?
The reason the KC is still here
after 76 years
is because if it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
It's cooked just with a little
bit of pink like I like my pork.
Very tender. I love the flavor
of the cranberry on top.
I don't know
where you could go in town
and get a stuffed pork chop
this good.
MAN:
It hasn't changed.
I think that is
the reason for their success.
FIERI: What a place!
Everything
from the sunken bar,
to the patent leather,
to the wagon-wheel lights.
I mean, it feels like you
stepped right back into 1962.
Great job.
Thanks for
keeping it going.
Well, thank you. Hopefully,
we got another 76 years.
Oh, I think you do.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up,
we're sticking to Bakersfield...
Ooh!
Yeah!
...making a spicy stop...
Habanero-mango chili.
...at a place
with their own Latin spin.
That's the twist.
So, I'm here in downtown
Bakersfield, California,
about a block away from
the famous Padre Hotel --
a place that I like to stay.
Now, they got
a lot of restaurants here --
Johnny Garlic's.
Shameless plug for me.
But they got a lot of taquerías.
So, when these two dudes
came together and said,
"Hey, we're gonna open up, like,
a Latin restaurant,"
they said,
"We don't want to do a taquería.
No, we want to do something
with a Latin/American fusion."
And that's what we got
right here at Mama Roomba.
Cheese empanadas --
pick it up.
It's one of the most unique
places in Bakersfield.
It's Mexican, it's
South American, it's Caribbean.
Tortilla soup, sea mussels --
pick it up, please.
WOMAN: Very eclectic menu.
It's like a vacation
on every plate.
FIERI: Thanks to this guy,
Chef Isaac Mancilla,
who's been fusing
these exotic flavors since 2005.
So, we're taking American items
and making them Latin
and Latin items
and making them gringo?
So, I try to mix it all together
to make something nice.
I think every dish
is pretty amazing.
Latin fried chicken.
The Latin fried chicken
is out of bounds.
It's nice and crispy,
tender inside.
WOMAN: And then you hit it
with the mango salsa.
It's the perfect combination.
What are we gonna
make first?
The Latin/American
fried chicken.
So, we're gonna make
the marinade for the chicken?
Yes.
Okay, hit it.
Cayenne pepper.
Granulated garlic.
Black pepper.
Salt.
Plain yogurt.
Do you have yogurt
in Mexican food?
That's the twist.
And the buttermilk.
Buttermilk?
You're gonna mix it all
together.
Okay.
And then I'm gonna put it
in the container.
And then we transfer
our chicken tenders.
How long
is this gonna marinate?
At least six hours.
What are we gonna
coat it in?
Just flour,
salt, and pepper.
Then we'll fry it.
Exactly.
Now what
are we gonna make?
Habanero-mango
chili sauce.
Habanero-mango chili.
He makes it sound good.
We start with water.
Drop some garlic
and habanero.
Brown sugar.
Tomatoes.
Bell peppers.
Red onions.
Molasses.
You use molasses
in Latin food?
Not really.
[ Laughs ]
Tamarind sauce.
Oh, tamarind sauce.
Apple vinegar.
Cumin.
Thyme.
Cinnamon.
And...?
And Dijon mustard.
Oh, yes!
Another kick.
Then at the end,
the mango.
How long
is this gonna cook down?
An hour.
And then later, we're gonna hit
it with an immersion blender.
An immersion blender.
Okay, let's go.
We got our chicken ready.
This is how many
come with an order?
Yes.
Mmm.
Chicken's got
a little bit of spice.
I think a lot of people,
they would call these
chicken tenders.
They're plump,
juicy, crunchy.
What I like the best about it --
the salsa's cold...
Yes.
...the chicken's hot.
Your mouth gets
a little bit spicy,
then it gets
a little sweet.
It's addicting.
Nice job.
Thanks.
The chicken is very crunchy
on the outside with the spices.
The sauce is amazing,
a little bite to it.
I love their food.
This is the pan-fried sea bass.
The ambience is wonderful.
FIERI: But the real show's
back in the kitchen...
Like Rico Suave.
That's Roomba?
...which is where this joint
gets its funky name.
Rumba is
a kind of dance.
Da-da, one-two, one-two.
Oh, is there a little kick
in there?
Yeah, like that.
No dance floor here,
but Isaac's busting out
some mean moves at the grill.
Tri-tip --
pick it up.
The tri-tip is delicious,
especially with
the Chimichurri sauce.
WOMAN: They serve it
on a sizzling skillet,
so when it hits the table,
it's really a head turner.
Okay,
what are we gonna make next?
Churrasco tri-tip.
So, we have the tri-tip.
And then we make
our seasoning.
Granulated garlic.
Paprika.
Black pepper.
Chili flakes.
Salt.
Brown sugar.
And a little...?
Thyme.
And gimme some...
Ooh!
Yeah!
Now you're getting
the rumba.
And then
we mix it all together.
So, now where do we put
the meat?
Oh, we're gonna tenderize?
With the tenderizer.
Cha-cha-cha?
Ah!
And now we pour the oil
over the top?
Yeah.
We let it marinate
for at least 12 hours.
And then we'll put that
on the grill?
Exactly.
Got it.
And then we're gonna
finish it in the oven.
In the oven.
All right, Chef,
what's next?
We're gonna make
our Chimichurri sauce.
I like this.
Cilantro.
Parsley.
The garlic.
We'll add black pepper.
Chili flakes.
Oregano.
Ground cloves.
Really? That much?
Mm-hmm.
Salt.
Water.
Okay.
White vinegar.
And the oil.
Thank you, Chef.
Let all these flavors
come together.
We are ready.
Let's plate our tri-tip.
We put on a bed of onions
and our tri-tip.
We put
the Chimichurri sauce on.
The flavors are great.
It's a nice medium-rare.
The meat's seasoned.
It's cooked great.
The freshness
of the Chimichurri.
The grilled onions
going along with it.
Lots of flavor,
lots of variety.
You put a lot of time
into it.
Can't beat it.
Nice job, buddy.
It's nice and spicy.
You cut into it,
it's nice and tender.
The Chimichurri sauce
is delicious.
MAN: The grilled onions with it
just adds to the whole meal.
It's amazing.
Atmosphere's great --
It makes you feel
like you're somewhere
in the Caribbean.
I enjoy
that you push the creativity.
Simple but nice.
Yeah, thank you.
Thank you, Chef.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Habanero-mango chili sauce.
Drop a little shoulder in
on that?
Say it one more time to the
camera. Tell it to the ladies.
Habanero-mango
chili sauce.
Yeah.
Making sexy food here.