Hey, I'm Guy Fieri, and we're
rolling out on a special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" in Italy.
This trip...
Oh!
...we're filling up
on the flavors of Florence.
It's delicious.
First, a serious spaghetteria.
I love this guy.
Keeping it in the family
for over 50 years.
Great food
with great people.
You're
the perfect example.
Then,
a second-generation chef...
You're a character, man.
...dishing out
his own twist on tradition.
I've never had a pasta
like that.
Plus,
a fiery, fresh pizzeria...
Geez.
You load that up.
...piling on
a true Italian experience.
Oh, that's killer, man.
From pasta to pollo...
The original
chicken nugget.
...get ready for some
of the best on the Boot.
Oh, two forks?
Yeah, you think
that's what I need, huh?
[ Horn honks ]
So, when you think
about the big cities in Italy,
what do you think of?
Well, of course, you got Rome,
you got Naples, you got Venice,
and in the top five,
right here in Florence.
And they've got it all --
the museums, the Duomo,
and, of course, restaurants.
You got pizzerias, osterias,
and old-school icon joints like
this place, Fratelli Briganti.
This is
not tourist restaurant,
but is Italian restaurant
for Italian people.
Everything they do is fresh.
Pronto.
The food is very good.
It's homemade every day.
FIERI: By this guy,
chef and owner Lido Briganti.
His dad
opened the place in 1960,
raising his four sons
in the biz.
And, today,
Lido's daughter, Ema,
follows the family tradition.
It's a cool name --
"Fratelli Briganti."
"Brothers of Briganti"?
Yeah. Yeah.
A name that literally means
"bandito" or "bandit."
Hmm? Bandito.
Bravo, bravo, bravo.
But no bad guys here.
Just happy customers.
How long
have you been coming here?
40 years.
WOMAN:
Spaghettini pomodoro fresco.
My favorite dish
is spaghettini with tomato.
And they're very know about
this dish in this restaurant.
All right.
So, what are we gonna make?
It's spaghettini
de Briganti.
"The spaghetti
of the house."
Yeah.
Okay. Let's go.
We're gonna remove the skin
from the tomatoes.
Okay.
Where did you
learn to cook, Chef?
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Laughs ]
He stole the job,
looking his brothers
and his father, and then...
So he watched
his brothers and his father,
so he stole the job
from them.
I love this guy.
Now we put them
in the colander.
So, let the water
drain out a little bit. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Next?
Cut the garlic.
Okay.
A little bit of salt.
Olive oil.
And that's
the whole foundation of this?
Yeah.
[ Speaking Italian ]
He's the boss.
Okay.
[ Hand slaps ]
Oh!
Now, the pasta that has
a little bit of texture
to the outside of it --
It's not thin and sheeny.
And that's the difference,
I think, in really great pasta.
Oh. So it goes
right to the plate, huh?
All three of us
are eating, I guess.
Chili flakes.
Parmesan cheese.
Olio.
Okay.
Olive oil.
Very good.
Oh, two forks?
Yeah, you think
that's what I need, huh?
Now he's Mr. Funny-Funny.
I've had
the exact same dish
in a lot
of Italian restaurants.
[ Speaking Italian ]
No. Not possible.
But the flavor
isn't as fresh.
[ Speaking Italian ]
The tomatoes taste like triple
the flavor of tomatoes.
The basil's sweet.
The cheese
is a little bit salty.
I knew
it was gonna be great,
but it shouldn't taste
that phenomenal,
but it really does.
Fantastic.
[ Laughs ]
For the guy
that didn't say anything
or understand
what I was saying,
now, for some reason,
he just --
That Rosetta Stone
just came through.
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughs ]
It's a simple dish,
but it's really delicious.
Here we go.
FIERI: What makes it
taste so good?
The first thing
is the fresh tomato,
and the second one
is the oil that they use.
I like Fratelli Briganti because
everything is fresh and good.
FIERI:
And just 'cause it's Italian
doesn't mean this joint
is only about pasta.
MAN: Pollo frito.
This is delicious.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: When we come back, we're
digging into this local take
on an American favorite.
This takes fried chicken
to a whole new level.
FIERI:
Here in Florence, Italy,
we're parked
at Fratelli Briganti,
a family-owned landmark
that's been serving up
some real-deal Italian
since the 1960s.
FIERI: Is this
truly authentic Italian?
Without question.
That's 'cause
this guy's in charge.
[ Speaking Italian ]
Lido Briganti, who's worked here
with his three brothers
since he was a kid.
The same smile now.
It's the same smile there.
Have you always wanted to be
in the restaurant business?
[ Speaking Italian ]
Si!
Yes.
Ay!
FIERI: And part of his menu
is a familiar American dish,
but with an Italian spin.
WOMAN: Pollo frito.
I'm having fried chicken
with fried vegetables.
It's a really crunchy chicken,
and inside,
the meat is really soft.
FIERI: What are
we gonna cook next?
Pollo frito.
Fried chicken?
Fried chicken.
This I got to see.
That's
what we're gonna do?
Is we're just gonna hack
this poor chicken.
The original
chicken nugget.
What's next, Chef?
[ Speaking Italian ]
All right.
[ Whistles ]
Look at how golden
that yolk is.
Organic?
Yeah.
Salt.
Si, si.
Buon secondo.
[ Laughs ]
I knew that's what he said.
"Buon secondo" means,
"He's a good second."
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
That's awesome.
All right. Now we're gonna
work on the vegetables.
[ Speaking Italian ]
What? What?
Zucchini.
The artichokes.
All right.
Grazie.
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
We're gonna make
a little batter
with some egg
and some flour,
a little touch
of some salt.
Acqua frizzante.
Sparkling water.
So, the veggies go in.
Mm-hmm.
And so, here's the thing
with this sparkling water,
is it adds
a little carbonation to it,
which makes the batter
nice and light.
That oil's hot.
So, the artichokes.
Zucchini.
Papas.
Run.
It's beautiful.
The oil was super-hot,
but he was able
to put everything in
in the correct order,
and it all
comes out perfectly.
Chef,
it's very beautiful.
[ Conversing in Italian ]
He knows.
[ Laughs ]
When did I lose control
of my show?
[ Laughs ]
It's hot.
The chicken's outrageous.
It's not overly seasoned.
It's just
tender, juicy chicken.
[ Speaking Italian ]
And then the artichokes.
It's not oily.
It's not greasy.
Cooked perfectly.
Real flavors.
You don't need
to dip this in anything.
Potatoes
are cut perfectly.
I mean,
everything is in balance.
Outrageous.
[ Speaking Italian ]
Oh!
Bandito.
[ Laughing ] Bandito.
Enjoy.
Chicken is crispy and soft.
I like very much.
It's very delicious.
If people want to have
a good Italian dinner,
they have to come
to Fratelli Briganti restaurant,
because it's
a real Italian kitchen.
Here's the thing.
When I told everybody
that I'm coming to Florence,
because it's great people
with great food --
You're
the perfect example.
EMA: [ Speaking Italian ]
And he's the example.
[ Speaking Italian ]
Will you be back?
Oh!
No, no.
Don't come back.
[ Laughs ]
"No, no, no.
Don't come back."
[ Laughter ]
I tell you, you got
to watch out for the bandit.
FIERI: Up next, a chef
who's mixing things up...
The term
was "bubbly nice"?
Bubbly nice.
...and taking local
to a whole new level.
When you're cooking
in here...
Yeah?
...this is your view.
So, it is really easy
to get lost in Florence.
I got to tell you --
between the narrow streets
and, well,
maybe making a wrong turn
on a one-way street a few times.
But don't worry.
We're finally here.
We're a few blocks away from the
central market to check a joint
where a son has carried on
his parents' tradition
and added
his own little twist to it.
This is La Cucina del Garga.
[ Speaking Italian ]
It's local. It's Tuscan.
Delicious.
It's just sublime.
Florentine food
is micro-regional.
Everybody cooks with
what they have around them.
FIERI:
And for Chef Alessandro Gargani,
it's a quick walk
to the market...
This is my garden.
...or stepping
out the back door.
You need a fresh herb, you
just go out there and grab it?
That's it.
This fresh fixation comes
from growing up in the biz.
Alessandro's parents opened
their first restaurant in 1979.
This is the second coming
of Garga.
Whoo-hoo!
FIERI: And he took over
this place in 2010.
The food here is great.
At times, I'm reluctant
to try new things -- not here.
Farfalle
with pistachio sauce.
It's my favorite thing.
Okay, Chef.
What are we making?
We're making the farfalle
with pistachio pesto.
We're gonna do fresh pasta.
Fantastic.
Let's go.
We have here semolina flour.
2.
We're gonna make
a hole in the middle.
Two cracked eggs.
Salt and oil.
Scramble the eggs inside.
Can't tell that he's made it
900,000 times or anything.
We're gonna use
this magic tool.
This is a magic tool?
Yeah, because it helps you
not get your hands so messy.
But now it's time
to get messy.
Okay.
This little guy --
We're gonna put to rest
for 30 minutes.
Wrap it in some plastic?
Wrapped in plastic, yes.
So, now we've let
the dough rest.
It's time for the pasta dough
to go through the machine
so we can achieve
a nice, thin sheet dough.
What are we making?
Farfalle.
You make simple squares
like this...
Okay.
...with a special tool
that makes fancy.
Otherwise, you can do
something else.
"Special tool
that makes fancy."
This is a special tool
that makes it look fancier.
And...
Yay!
...that's the farfalle.
They're beautiful.
It's kind of like
tying a bow on a present.
But we're not pinching them
too tight,
because then they become
mushy in the middle
and they
won't cook through.
Exactly.
But now let's make the sauce.
Okay.
Lime zest, garlic.
Fresh mint,
extra virgin olive oil.
And now's the rest
of the ingredients.
So, you got pistachio,
Parmigiano,
extra virgin olive oil,
pinch of salt.
[ Processor whirring ]
Okay.
Extra virgin olive oil --
just like a tablespoon.
Nothing.
Pinch of salt.
Then we're gonna kick it up
with mint.
Did you just Emeril
this dish?
No.
Oh, you did.
You just Emeril'ed it up.
I watch it. I watch it.
It's okay.
I watch it.
He's experienced.
Want to make sure.
He's the king.
And then the fire
goes on for about 30 seconds
in order the mint
to get crispy.
Mint to get crispy.
Crispy. We like it.
And we're gonna add
the pistachio that we made.
The pasta.
We just toss
the pasta inside.
Not too much.
Plate it.
Add some cherry tomatoes.
Then roasted pistachio
on top of it.
Chopped parsley.
Enjoy.
Okay.
It's really bright
and refreshing and unique.
Love the pistachio.
The texture of the pesto
is exactly how I like it.
And you make your own pasta.
And you know what?
It's delicious.
I've never had Italian food like
this in America or in Italy.
How do you describe
this food?
WOMAN: Simple and flavorful,
elegant.
Elegant goes in there?
Okay.
Yeah.
The atmosphere is sensational.
So, what time
do you open?
We open at dinner only.
Dinner only?
Yes. For me, it's all about
quality versus quantity.
Tagliatelle del "Magnifico."
WOMAN: You can always find
a little something
in every dish
that's innovative.
WOMAN #2: I'm eating
the pasta del magnifico.
The flavor's just amazing.
It's completely unexpected.
Tagliatelle del "Magnifico"
is one of the recipes that
my father was very famous for.
Okay. So, now we're gonna
roll out the pasta.
There we go.
Look at that.
And now
we're gonna prepare the sauce
that is gonna blow
your mind apart.
Blow my mind apart.
Yep.
Okay.
We start
with heavy cream.
Orange zest.
Lemon zest.
And this is hearty zest.
I mean, this isn't
little, petite zest.
Yes.
We're gonna give it
to them. Okay.
So, yes.
Mint leaves.
Add a shot of Stravecchio,
Italian Cognac.
Now we're gonna let
the sauce reduce to half.
I like this.
See how now
it's bubbly nice?
The term
was "bubbly nice"?
Bubbly nice.
We're gonna add
the Parmesan cheese.
Ooh.
Nice and tight.
Pasta
is getting translucent.
Mmm.
Trans-lunchy.
Nice.
I love this pasta.
Tagliatelle del "Magnifico"
are ready.
Buon apetito.
Thank you very much.
The mint
with the orange and lemon --
It's reminiscent
of a cocktail.
[ Chuckles ]
Get a little bit
of the alcohol.
When you want to kind of
mix your palate up a little
and you want to get
something rich
with a lot of flavor
and a lot of creativity,
this is your dish.
I've never had a pasta
like that.
Thank you.
It's a new plate.
It's different but excellent.
WOMAN: And a little bit
of oranges -- That's the twist.
And who would have
thought of that?
This is the place
where I bring people
when they come to visit
from America.
The thing
I really like the most --
You're a character, man.
Thank you.
You are an experience,
my friend.
Thank you.
You are an experience.
Nicely done.
Oh.
FIERI: Coming up at
our last stop in Florence...
FIERI: You try first.
We try together.
...a taste
of a different Italian city...
So, you get this salami
from Naples?
Yeah.
Everything is from Naples.
...fired up old-school-style.
I'd love to do the show
for you and everything,
but I got wood
I got to work.
So, my final leg of this awesome
"Triple D" tour of Florence,
I'm over
the Ponte Vecchio Bridge
on the older side of Florence.
Now, what would you get
over here?
Well, you got antique shops,
you got businesses
for the locals,
and, of course,
I find a pizzeria.
And not just any pizzeria.
I'm talking an old-school,
real-deal Neapolitan pizzeria.
That's right.
This is Il Gusta Pizza.
Guys, the caprese.
Blew my mind.
From the minute you walk in the
door here, it's just amazing.
It's kind of what you're looking
for when you come to Italy.
MAN: It's really authentic.
You've got the four brothers
running around back there.
FIERI:
Those are the Brothers Maruca,
who moved to Florence
when their brother Pasquale
opened their first joint in '04.
Started with
the Gusta Panino.
We make sandwich.
And after,
we do Gusta Pizza.
We do fresh every time.
Calabrese.
MAN: This pizza is amazing.
It's the best pizza
I've ever had.
What kind of machine
is this?
It's an [Speaking Italian]
It's like a brace
like this.
You know. Like...
[ Both breathing deeply ]
We gonna make dough?
Yeah.
Water.
Salt.
That's a lot of salt.
Now?
The ester.
Live yeast.
Just two minutes.
Okay.
Now we open it up.
And Caputo.
Caputo --
It's the best flour.
It's the best.
Okay.
Let this go for 25 minutes,
and we pull it out.
Yes.
We put oil on top.
Okay.
And leave it
for five minutes.
And after,
we do the ball for the pizza.
Then we make the pizza.
We start now with the Calabrese
pizza with the spicy salami.
FIERI: And that is
just tomato sauce?
Solamente?
Yep.
Parmigiano cheese.
Okay.
Mozzarella.
Salamino piccante.
It kind of
tastes like pepperoni.
Geez.
You load that up, buddy.
Basil.
You but the basil
before it goes in the oven?
Yeah. That's my,
you know, roasted basil.
Basil.
Extra virgin olive oil.
You help me?
Yes. Absolutely.
Ready?
Coming.
Where?
Here. It's like...
Now it's ready.
All these burns --
That's part of the program.
Beautiful.
You can test.
Nice, little crust
on the bottom of it.
[ Breathes deeply ]
I love that you put oil
on the basil.
You definitely
get that perfume.
Yeah.
Oh, that's killer, man.
Okay. You try.
Tell me what you think.
I think it's really hot.
[ Laughter ]
Your Calabrese.
It's unbelievable --
gooey and cheesy and creamy.
Everybody knows Pizzeria Luigi
in San Diego.
We've done it on "Triple D,"
I think, twice.
Luigi's been with me
on this "Triple D" experience
in Florence.
What do you think?
It got the nice bite.
The salami's perfect.
You can't find this type
of salami back in the States.
How's the crust?
The crust is perfect.
Got good chew?
Yeah.
Nice chew to it.
For you. Gusta Pizza.
The best Italian pizza
is Naples pizza --
original pizza.
FIERI: And pizza's
just one of the things
they're making Naples-style.
Okay.
The calzone, a number one.
It's got ricotta cheese
and sweet sausage in it.
Very good.
Now what are we making?
We're making
calzone Napolitano.
"Calzone from Naples"?
Yeah.
Ricotta.
Parmigiano cheese.
And a little mozzarella.
Now we do
the slice of salami.
It's salami Napolitano
from Naples.
Okay.
Sweet salami.
So, you get this salami
from Naples?
Everything is from Naples.
Black pepper.
And that's it?
Yep.
Wait.
We put the sauce on now?
When it cooks?
Yep.
I've made a lot of calzones.
I've never seen it this way.
And then we're gonna put
the basil up on top?
Yep.
Okay. This is completely --
I'm out.
And a little bit of olive oil.
Okay.
No, this is all you
this time, homey.
All right.
And how long?
Two minutes and a half,
three minutes.
Should be good.
Is it ready?
Ready.
Let's do it.
Very nice.
I like that little
sauce-on-top technique, man.
I bet you,
inside, it's not hot.
I think it's hot.
You try first.
You try.
No, you are --
No. I bet --
I'm the one
that made the bet.
You try first.
We try together.
[ Muffled ] That's hot.
Good.
[ Normal voice ]
There's a lot of depth to this.
You've got great crust.
You got some nice flavor
coming from the salami.
I love the tomato sauce
on top.
And the ricotta.
This has got
a little bit of tang to it.
This guy's the real deal.
Thank you.
Thank you, brother.
Very nice.
The calzone is for you.
Fluffy. It was light,
but creamy and salty.
I keep coming back for more.
Napoli and Calabrese.
You come in here --
It's the camaraderie, as well.
You sit with someone else
you don't even know.
It's always packed.
Everyone shares. It's great.
Just in case you don't
have a job in the States...
I come back.
...you can come here.
Promise.
Where do I start?
You start in the oven.
Can you?
Let me get it.
Yes.
I'd love to do the show
for you and everything,
but I got wood
I got to work.
Man, was that
a great Italian tour or what?
But don't you worry --
There's funky joints
all over this world.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If we put some blond hair on
you, you could take some heat.
Sorry.
I need to work.
I'm sorry. Okay.
Ricotta.
I just got smacked down
on my own show.
[ Laughs ]