I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoo!
We're driving
to the desert...
That's how we roll, man.
We got to get crazy back here.
...to an Arizona, packed,
culinary oasis...
It feeds not just your stomach.
It feeds your soul.
...in Scottsdale.
This is gonna be
like magic.
A market-restaurant
mash-up...
If I cry during this,
please don't hold it
against me.
...serving up a scene
right out of Italy.
Basta! Basta!
Hey, hey, hey!
Then just up the road...
Can I take it?
...a southern barbecue
pit stop...
Look at that fat.
There's juicy.
...serving up grub,
gifts, and gas?
This is at a gas station,
ladies and gentlemen.
And in Phoenix...
I'm telling you what.
This is prime time, buddy.
...a visit to
the Burger Whisperer...
Bla-ow!
That's what
a good burger does?
That's what a good bur--
it should speak to you.
...getting crazy
with his creations.
You got issues,
and I like it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I love Arizona.
I mean Scottsdale, Phoenix --
you got it all down here.
Great weather, tons of things
to do in the desert,
and then there's the food.
So, what am I looking for?
Some Italian.
And not just some
everyday Italian.
I'm talking about a joint
where the dude
bakes his bread
and he makes
his own prosciutto.
This is
Andreoli's Italian Grocer.
[ Speaks Italian ]
MAN #1: It feels like,
when you walk in to Andreoli,
like you've walked into
a small town in Italy.
Here's
your grilled calamari.
It's like going to
your family's house for dinner
if your family
were crazy Italians
and had mad kitchen skills.
FIERI:
Like Giovanni Scorzo,
whose wife, Linda,
studied in Italy
and brought back,
well, more than just souvenirs.
You meet her,
then you come here.
And then we open our restaurant
after three years.
Then, after nearly 20 years
of running full-scale
Italian joints,
building this market in '07.
This is a real-deal
Italian market.
We have 80 different
kind of cheeses,
prosciutto, salami,
all the pastries.
MAN #2: Fish, seafood, pizza,
whatever you want.
I'm having
the Sempronio sandwich.
Sempronio.
MAN #1:
And it's just fantastic.
The prosciutto is what you
would expect to find in Italy.
Prosciutto's, like,
this thinly sliced pork.
When someone told me that
there was an Italian market
that made their own prosciutto,
I said, "I got to see this."
SCORZO:
The big pig -- porco.
If I cry during this,
please don't hold it
against me.
Got to take
the bone out of this
to get into
this curing process
'cause this is gonna go
how long?
This is gonna go for a year?
At least one year, yeah.
And now we're going to...
Goes in the sea salt
from Sicily.
Just a tiny bit.
This is ready to [whistles]
How long?
40 days.
It's gonna pull out
a bunch of the moisture.
After 40 days,
we take it out.
We put it in fresh water.
We dry with paper towel.
I like it.
We make a marinade
with Vino Rosso.
Is that good or more?
Basta! Basta!
Hey, hey, hey!
You can have too much red wine?
Fresh garlic.
Black pepper.
And we grab these.
Beautiful.
We just push that.
This is gonna go
in the refrigerator.
For 45 days?
Like a month,
is enough.
Now we're gonna lock it down
with the fat and the flour.
Look at that.
Get after it.
Fresh ground pepper.
Yeah.
Smell.
No!
"Smell."
[ Laughs ]
Where did you want me
to put it?
In my tummy.
[ Laughs ]
Go like this.
And that's to seal up
the bottom
so it doesn't rot
on the outside.
I take the rest of this
and just use this for the hair.
Tie the leg.
We will go like this.
Hey!
Put your finger there.
Your finger.
I know better than
to put my finger in there
when you're tying it.
Okay.
I get --
More beautiful.
Ow!
Hey!
Just hang that.
Thank you.
This is gonna go night-night
for a year.
Perfecto.
Okay.
Now, this is
the really cool part.
To tell if they're done --
This is the femur of the horse,
correct?
They shave it down.
Okay?
Now, watch this.
Perfect.
Beautiful.
It smells just like
fresh-cut prosciutto.
I like it.
Then we can start...
All right.
Tighten it nice.
Making it nice.
Then we start from here.
There we go.
So it's so thin,
and it's got one side.
That's fantastic.
All right,
let's make the sandwich.
I'm putting mozzarella.
Roasted peppers.
And we'll go like this.
And then boom, boom, boom.
Buon appetito!
Mmm! Very simple.
Great bread.
Incredible meat.
You don't mess it up
with other things.
You get the experience
that Italians
that slow down
at lunchtime,
take the time
to enjoy the food, relax.
That's what this sandwich is.
What it's supposed to be.
It's dynamite.
Thank you. Thank you.
WOMAN: Prosciutto sandwich,
the Sempronio.
Prosciutto
is almost like butter.
It just melts in your mouth.
I think the best part
is the homemade mozzarella.
No matter what comes out of the
kitchen, it's amazing.
What do you think
makes the food so great?
The passion, for one,
the creativity.
Calamari alla griglia.
They do an amazing job.
They're very talented.
FIERI: Even with
your basic meat and potatoes,
Scorzo family style.
SCORZO: Bollito.
The best beef I've ever had.
FIERI: When we come back...
So simple,
but so fulfilling.
It was like having a dish
at your grandma's house.
FIERI: If you're at
Andreoli Italian Grocery,
you're in
Scottsdale, Arizona,
but you might not
even know it.
You could definitely be
in Italy.
'Cause everything
they're selling is imported,
except what they're making
in the back.
SCORZO: Here is
beautiful Sempronio.
I know it's always
gonna be delicious.
FIERI: All right, chef,
what are we gonna make next?
We're gonna make the
bollito di carne di manzo.
Bollito di carne.
Does "bollito" mean "boil,"
or what does it mean?
Boiled.
What does "manzo" mean?
Beef. Young beef.
First, we start with the...
Peppercorn.
...peppercorn.
Do you have to
put it in like this?
Like-a magic?
Well, it is a magician.
Yes.
Our onions
sticked with cloves.
I know. Grazie.
He's making me
smell everything in this.
Carrots?
No, I'm not
smelling carrots.
[ Laughter ]
Nice garlic clove.
Bay leaves from Italy.
Yes.
Then we have celery.
Italian parsley.
Thyme.
[ Whistles ]
Bring this to boil,
then we add the meat.
How long is
the meat gonna go?
From 3 to 3 1/2 hours.
And then we add some salt
to taste.
The last 20 minutes,
we add the potatoes.
So, they build the flavor.
FIERI:
And to dip into that broth,
well, you got to have
an authentic Italian staple.
Now we're gonna
make the bread.
We start with water.
And this?
This is a starter.
Wow.
Whew. Whew!
35 years old.
35 years.
It's making
my eyes water.
It smells like
gorgonzola cheese.
I mean, it is pungent.
It's fantastic.
Every time you make the bread,
you save the starter.
Oh, yeah.
This is like gold.
Now we put in the water.
Yeast.
Fresh yeast.
Yeah.
And then
we add the flour.
Now the salt.
Okay, so how long
is this gonna go for?
Like, maybe 10, 15 minutes.
Then we'll put it
on the bench.
We're gonna make a ball,
put it in a sheet pan.
We're gonna let them rise
to double the size,
and then
we're gonna stretch.
And then to
the wood-fired oven.
400 degrees.
Look at that. Beautiful.
Can I take a piece.
That is delicious.
I get the smell of that starter
right off the bat.
Nice and airy and light.
Excellent.
Okay, we go over
the bollito.
We're gonna go
to the finish line.
Finish line.
Easy!
Hey, hey!
[ Whistles ]
Wow.
Nice.
You can put the salsa verde,
which is Italian parsley,
garlic, peppers, anchovies,
pickles, boiled eggs.
Go like this, and then
a piece of the bread.
So simple.
So basic.
But so fulfilling.
It feeds not just your stomach.
It feeds your soul.
You just dip a little bit
of that homemade bread
in the broth.
You get a little bit
of the thyme,
a little bit of the celery,
a little touch of
the peppercorn.
This market,
this piece of Italy
would be a reason
to move here.
Amazing.
Bravo. Thank you.
I'll have the bollito.
Thank you.
It's full of flavor.
The meat is super tender.
The broth is light,
and the potato was delicious.
Authentic Italian food.
You miss Italy
very much when I'm here.
Nice job.
The real deal.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up in Phoenix...
Pew!
Oh, that's how it goes?
...a burger chef
pushing the limits...
It takes the regular everyday
burger to another level.
...turning his passion
into an art form.
You've seen it
a million times.
He's putting it all together
right here.
So, I'm here
in Phoenix, Arizona,
right by Paradise Valley,
to check out a joint
where this guy's doing
some crazy things to burgers.
Let's see.
He's putting eggs on burgers.
He's cooking burgers in booze.
He's even deep-frying burgers.
This is
Paradise Valley Burger Co.
MAN: If you love burgers,
this is the place to come,
not just in
the state of Arizona,
but all over.
The Beach House Burger.
MAN:
The creativity and craftsmanship
that goes into
making their burgers --
I couldn't even duplicate it
if my life depended on it.
FIERI:
And they're all the brain child
of chef and owner Bret Shapiro,
who opened this joint in 2011.
A good burger should...
When you're like, Bla-ow!
That's what
a good burger does?
It should speak to you.
And speaking of burgers...
Country-Fried Burger
for you.
The Country-Fried Burger
is another one of my favorites.
Green chili, bacon, cream sauce
on top of deep-fried patties --
That's America right there.
What's gonna be in
the Country-Fried Burger?
We're gonna start off
with the country-fried gravy.
We're gonna add
some olive oil,
diced red onion,
sliced jalapeños,
sliced garlic.
Generous
on the salt and pepper.
Shake up the pan a little bit.
Get them nice and tender.
Would you like a towel?
Monster hands.
Been doing this
since I was 15 years old.
There you go.
Okay,
so the gravy's going.
Gonna hit it
with our heavy cream now.
Now, this is gonna
simmer down.
Simmer down, now!
Simmer down, now.
Cook it for about
15, 20 minutes,
got to reduce it
by half.
Okay.
Add our fresh thyme.
Now we hit it
with the immersion blender.
And then that's gonna go
on top of the burger.
How many patties
in the burger?
Each burger's 4 ounces,
so it's gonna get
two 2-ounce patties.
Boom. That's my sweet spot
right there.
There you go.
Why did you decide to do it
in this fashion --
two-ounce patties?
I wanted to maximize
the char for each burger.
Awesome.
Let's see you go.
Tan it. Tan it.
Tan it.
What is the sun-tan lotion
you're spraying on it?
A little bit
of heavy cream.
Heavy cream
in a mystery bottle.
Exactly.
Flour, flour, flour.
Patties going in.
Pew!
Oh, that's how it goes?
That's how we roll, man.
We got to get crazy back here.
You got issues,
and I like it.
Next up...
So I square up my buns
so they stick to
the flat top.
Wait, wait. Time out.
You get the buns in round.
Yes, sir.
Then you cut
all the buns square.
Exactly right.
You want to toast
the whole --
The whole caboodle.
Start with a little
bit of lettuce to
protect the brioche.
I'm gonna add our
country-fried burger patties.
Double the patty up.
I like this.
Now we're gonna add
our gravy.
Little bit of fresh thyme.
You're into your thyme, huh?
No thyme! [time]
Tomatoes.
Fried onions.
And that's all she wrote.
For the Country-Fried Burger.
You got a beach towel?
Beach towel?
Of course, my man.
I just listened to you talk
about how you make this burger.
Cutting the bun
so you can get full contact.
Making the patties thin
so you can put a nice crust.
It's legit.
It's enthusiastic.
It takes the regular everyday
burger to another level.
I mean, it really is, man.
It's great.
Awesome, dude.
I appreciate that.
MAN:
It's very filling.
It actually leaves you
wanting more, though.
It's so delicious.
[ Chuckles ]
MAN:
I'm married to a chef,
and even she'll admit
that she can't cook burgers
nearly as well
as Paradise Valley Burger Co.
Your burger
interpretive dance.
What would it look like?
Start with the nose plug.
Work its way down.
That's where it's at.
Slowly switch.
Add some onions.
Line dance.
There we go.
You've seen it
a million times.
He's putting it all together
right here.
One minute
till burgers are done.
MAN: Sometimes you see something
that's just like,
"Wow, I never would have
imagined that in a burger."
SHAPIRO:
Got a Booze Burger and slaw.
So what are we making?
Green chili, bacon,
vodka cream sauce
for the Booze Burger.
Green chili, bacon,
vodka cream sauce.
Okay, get into it.
All right.
First, we're gonna start with
a little bit of olive oil.
Render down the bacon.
Cook it like it's...
Hot!       Hot!
Hot!                        Hot!
That's awesome.
Gonna drop in
our sliced red onion.
Okay.
Jalapeños.
This is like
an Arizona breath mint
more or less, man.
Get our garlic going.
[ Whistles ]
Once that's sweated down,
we're gonna add
some vodka to it.
We're gonna add
our heavy cream.
Get some sound effects.
[ Glugging ]
Nice.
Salt and pepper.
They're brothers.
They're best friends.
So, you
roasted the peppers...
Yep.
seeded, stemmed them,
skinned them.
Exactly right.
Okay.
And now
a bunch of cilantro.
Blend it.
Next up?
We're gonna pickle
the Fresno chilies.
Very nice.
A little bit
of sugar here.
This is liquid smoke.
Whiskey.
Okay.
Give it two days to pickle.
We're ready to serve them.
And that's what it is?
Yes, sir.
Now we're gonna make
a classic beer batter.
Start off with
a little bit of amber beer.
So far, we've used vodka.
We've used whiskey.
And here comes the beer.
The three food groups,
as I like to call them.
A little bit
of salt and pepper,
add our flour,
and mix it all together.
Next up,
we cook this burger.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Salt and pepper.
Now we're gonna
beer-batter our patties,
and then drop them
in the deep fryer
for about 2 1/2 minutes.
Okay. Let's get
our beer-battered patties.
[ Whistles ]
Add our green chili, bacon,
vodka, cream sauce.
And finally,
our pickled Fresno chilies.
Hands down,
what makes that burger --
those Fresno chilies.
I agree, man.
You got all kinds of
great crunch,
salt, a little spice
dropping in there.
You've got
a passion for it,
and it comes out
in the burger, man.
You're about to make
a grown man cry.
I'm telling you what,
this is prime time, buddy.
The Booze Burger is such
a perfect combination.
It's magic.
This is my buddy Taylor
from Rigid Lights.
He lives here.
What do you think,
brother?
Wicked.
Chili, burger, bread.
I'm usually a salad guy.
You know that.
Yes, I've --
lots of salads.
You can tell.
Heavy on the salads.
The sauce --
What's the sauce again?
Yeah.
It's awesome.
[ Laughs ]
It's a winner
every single time.
Oh, I need one of these
for the next "Triple D" shoot.
Swap keys for the day?
You know it.
Nice.
FIERI: Up next, we're hopping
over to Scottsdale...
I'm impressed.
...to fill up
at a gas station...
Now, that's a winning trick
right there.
...on some
high-octane barbecue.
Just the little touches like
that make it go over the top.
So, to wrap up this
Arizona "Triple D" tour,
I'm at a gas station,
and not just any gas station.
They also have a car wash,
a phenomenal gift shop,
and restaurant.
And not just any restaurant.
One that is serving up,
from what I hear,
competition-style barbecue.
This is Tom's Thumb.
Pulled pork sandwich is up.
MAN:
I've eaten barbecue all over.
This is by far and above
the best.
Here's your barbecue tacos.
I call it a hidden jewel.
WOMAN: We've known there's
a gas station-car wash here,
but we had no idea that
there was this thing going on
in the inside.
FIERI: This fuel-and-food biz
was launched
by chef and former E.R. doc
Kipp Lasseter in 2012.
Who designed this
with you?
My son-in-law.
He's been in the restaurant
business his whole life.
Then we started to talk.
"Well, let's put up
a barbecue place.
Then let's sell
high-octane gas."
And then, of course,
the women like all the gifts,
so we put that
in there.
But hang on a sec.
Back it up.
Let's get back
to that barbecue.
The brisket sandwich is up.
Very mouth-watering, very juicy,
has its own original spices.
What are we gonna make?
Well, we're gonna make
the rub first.
For the...?
Brisket.
And we're gonna start
with brown sugar.
Oh, my goodness.
Then we add paprika,
kosher salt.
That much
red chili flake?
Absolutely.
I've made a lot of rubs.
That's more chili flake
than I've ever seen
go in a rub.
Cumin powder, garlic,
cayenne pepper,
and black pepper.
We mix it all together.
You done
weeding out the lumps?
Yeah, yeah, we are.
All right,
so, we got some brisket.
Trim the fat.
Let me jump in here.
Okay, you do it.
If you cut your fingers,
I can help you there.
[ Laughs ]
Now we'll rub the brisket.
You actually get some
of the juices of that
meat in the rub.
Are we gonna let this
sit for a bit
before we drop it in
or go right to the smoker?
No, we wrap it
and let it sit overnight.
How long does it smoke?
About 12 hours.
All right, so we're gonna
slice this brisket up.
We go across the grain.
Look at that fat.
Just juicy.
Mmm.
Texas toast,
toasted on both sides.
Aioli...
Then we put some
good, old brisket on this.
Then we put some pickles,
a few onions,
and we just simply
put this on top,
wrap it up,
mash it down so it all fits.
[ Laughs ]
And that's all she wrote.
Absolutely.
What I think is interesting
is the aioli.
A little bit of that creaminess
coming through.
Pickle is a must-have.
And what barbecue sauce
is this?
That is Kansas City.
Okay.
Great smoke on it.
That pull-apart tender.
Love the Texas toast.
Just holds it together.
Nice job, doctor.
Yes, sir.
I like the way he...
operates.
[ Chuckles ]
Sliced brisket sandwich
here for you.
It just melts in your mouth
when you bite into it.
MAN:
The pickle and onion together
just really complement
the flavor of the brisket
itself.
This guy
does look familiar.
This is our good buddy Aaron May
from Over Easy.
Remember that joint?
How many new projects
in the Phoenix area
are you doing?
You got five Over Easys.
The Yacht Club, The Lodge.
Is there one called
The Good Wood?
Yeah.
Okay, so let's talk about
this joint.
I'm eating the brisket.
It's so good.
Everything about this place
is great.
FIERI:
Including what they've got
on the shelves.
Here you can buy wine.
Good wine.
No, great wine.
I'm impressed.
Nothing tells you
you love her
like a gift
from a gas station.
Or a plateful of pig.
All right,
the Pigs and Grits is up.
It's pulled pork.
I can't get enough of it.
What are we making?
Kansas City barbecue sauce.
for the Pigs and Grits.
Okay.
We first put in the butter.
Nice garlic.
[ Whistles ]
Chopped onions.
and then
the secret ingredient --
some minced pineapple.
Really?
Separately, we mix tomato sauce,
some molasses.
I dig it.
You got brown sugar
going in,
and then
we put the mustard.
Reconstituted pepper puree.
A little hot sauce.
Okay.
Worcestershire sauce.
Wor-shire-shire-shire.
Black pepper.
Chili powder.
Sea salt.
And last but not least...
Cayenne pepper.
And that's gonna get
dumped in on top.
Yes, sir.
How long are we gonna
let this cook down?
About 10 minutes.
And the last step?
We put this
in a hotel pan...
Okay.
and then we put it in the smoker
for about an hour.
You smoke
your barbecue sauce?
Absolutely.
Now, that's a winning trick
right there.
And now we're going to...
Deep-fry some good pork.
Just pulled
out of the smoker.
So we're gonna put some
beautiful grits there,
beautiful crispy pork.
Nice and moist.
Then we put some
Kansas City barbecue sauce,
cheddar, mozzarella,
menonita
and then we put this
in the Salamander.
Let that cheese get
good, little melt on it.
Okay.
We add jalapeño bacon bits,
chopped chives here.
This is at a gas station,
ladies and gentlemen,
just in case anybody's
just tuning in right now.
Good texture on the grits.
Nice little crunch
from the pork.
Got a little southern
grit soufflé going here.
Yes, sir.
Love that jalapeño bacon --
Just the little touches
like that
make it go over the top.
Well done, man.
Pigs and Grits here.
I've had grits a lot,
but never grits
that taste like this.
WOMAN: And the cheese
and the jalapeño bacon.
Mmm!
Amazing.
We got Tom's Brisket Stack.
As many restaurants
as I've eaten in my life,
this is up there
at the top.
Come fill up and get gas.
Brother, nice job.
All right, thank you.
Really nice job.
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
My inclination
is just to look at the camera
and make the most bizarre face
I possibly can.
Okay, ready?
In 5, 4, 3, 2...
[ Laughter ]