Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
This is gonna be good.
...we're going
coast to coast...
One of my many talents.
...for some killer
cultural cuisine.
Something funky, something
a little off the beaten path.
In Los Angeles,
California...
There's a lot
going on here.
...an authentic taste
of the Big Easy...
It is like
I'm in N'awlins.
...smack-dab in the middle
of Chinatown.
That is outrageous.
No, it really it is.
Then in East L.A...
We just
dropped the hammer!
...a funky fusion joint
spicing up Far-East flavor...
I'm ripping
that one off, man.
...with a south-of-the-border
spin.
This just turned into
a gigantic Mexican maki roll.
And in Charlotte,
North Carolina...
En garde.
...a one-of-a-kind pizzeria...
You learn something new
every day.
...serving up
a slice of Serbia.
Yes, sir.
Yes, Serbian.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I got one for you.
Why would a dude
from New Orleans
that's been living
in Los Angeles
for the last 18 years
decide to open a Cajun-Creole
joint in old Chinatown?
Because of...
the smoker?
This, I got to see.
Welcome to
the Little Jewel of New Orleans.
Chaurice is up.
It's amazing how delicious
this place is.
Po'boy
and half and half.
Marcus is definitely bringing
New Orleans to L.A.
in a big way.
FIERI: And when Louisiana native
Marcus Christiana-Beniger
started looking
for the right kitchen
to turn out a New Orleans menu,
well, it led him
right to Chinatown.
Southeast Louisiana --
We smoke a lot.
You name it -- Tasso seasoning
ham, boudin, andouille.
So, it's important to us
that we have a smoker
of some size,
and any Chinese restaurant
worth its salt
is gonna have a large one.
In 2014,
he hit the jackpot.
So, the main reason
to get this joint
is because
of a big kitchen.
Big kitchen,
large smoker.
[ Echoing ]
Can...you...hear me?
MAN:
[ Echoing ] No.
[ Laughter ]
Half and half po'boy.
I'm sitting here
with Miss Alice Wong,
who was Miss Chinatown
this year.
How do the folks in Chinatown
feel about this crazy Cajun
opening up this joint
in an old Chinese restaurant?
It's awesome.
It's definitely welcome.
This food is
about as authentic as it gets.
Cochon de Lait.
Today, I'm having
the Cochon de Lait.
It's absolutely delicious.
Pork, pork, pork, pork, pork,
pork...in a po'boy.
First off,
we're gonna get our rub going.
Our house Creole seasoning
right here.
Dark chili powder.
Some light chili powder.
Cayenne.
We're gonna finish off
with some salt.
We're gonna take the pork and
make about 12 to 15 incisions.
Then slide
whole toes of garlic.
This is gonna
get a chance
to break down and really perfume
all the way through this.
Now green Tabasco pepper.
So, I'm just gonna cover
all of it.
Ooh, there you go,
right in there.
We're gonna put our
chicken stock in on the sides,
and then finally, we're gonna
finish it off with our rub.
Nice, big, fat coating
up on top.
You should really think about
opening up a Cajun joint.
[ Chuckles ]
We're gonna cover it
with plastic and then foil --
make sure we got
a really tight seal on that.
Cook it for 8½ to 12 hours
around 230 to 250.
What's up next?
Creole slaw.
We got cabbage.
Shredded carrots,
some shredded white onions.
Gonna finish that off
with some sliced green onions.
Lightly toss.
Our wet ingredients are
Blue Plate mayonnaise,
a New Orleans
regional staple,
our Creole
house blend again,
Creole mustard, and then lastly,
apple-cider vinegar.
Go ahead
and whisk this in.
And then we'll add
our dressing.
Blue Plate mayonnaise,
dress it with shredded cabbage.
Use that cabbage
as a short of buffer.
Then we put our slaw
directly right on there.
It's a small sandwich.
Top that
with some pickles.
Rough-chopped parsley there,
and again, some green onions.
Copious amounts
of our pork.
Liberal amounts
of hot sauce there.
We're just gonna go ahead
and wrap this bad boy.
And that's all she wrote.
And that's it.
That's a real-deal
po'boy, man.
Pork's tender,
seasoning's balanced.
The highlight of the sandwich,
for me, is that slaw.
The slaw is righteous.
It all comes together
incredibly well.
People that don't understand
what a po'boy is,
we're talking about a tremendous
amount of tradition,
and there's a lot
going on here.
Real deal. Delicious.
Working on
Cochon de Lait.
There is an insane amount
of meat on this sandwich.
It's super tender and flavorful
and juicy.
It's so good.
My good buddy
Chef Phillip Franklin Lee.
I grew up in L.A.
Chinatown is
a spot in L.A.
where, you know,
you can taste the soul.
So, it fits?
I think
it actually fits here.
There's no other place
that's like Little Jewel in L.A.
FIERI:
That's 'cause we're talking more
than just a restaurant here.
Also got a nice, little
marketplace going on inside.
MAN: You can get all kinds
of regional products here --
all the ingredients --
all the beans, all the spices,
and the rices
and everything nices.
This is Evey,
and Evey actually is on my team
from "Guy's Grocery Games,"
is the one that recommended
this joint.
EVEY: It's amazing.
I'm trying to find
an apartment close by.
[ Laughs ]
But not too close
'cause I'd be here every day
picking up this dish.
CHRISTIANA-BENIGER:
Crawfish Mac is up.
Not your average mac and cheese.
Totally blew my mind.
FIERI: It's not good...
it's not great,
it's outstanding.
And that's coming up next.
Out of bounds.
FIERI: The Little Jewel
might be in the heart
of L.A.'s Chinatown,
but its soul lives
in New Orleans.
Not the kind of place you'd find
in the middle of Chinatown.
Blackened chicken.
FIERI: That's 'cause
Chef Marcus has a handle
on the Big Easy mix
of Cajun and Creole,
and there is a difference.
The Creole side of things --
it's not as spicy.
There is
more of a subtlety,
whereas Cajun food
is definitely spicy.
Either way,
here it's all about comfort.
It's all about
sticking to your ribs,
and this is what this food does.
Love the Crawfish Mac N Cheese.
It's very cheesy and comforting.
Crawfish Mac N Cheese.
So, we're gonna start off here
with some butter.
We're gonna caramelize
some onions here,
along with some garlic,
and just let that go
until they go clear.
Now we're gonna take
our heavy cream and curdle it.
You're going to curdle
the heavy cream?
Absolutely.
With some fresh lemon juice.
It's gonna mix better
with the cheese,
and it's also
gonna break down
all the elements combined into
the sauce that we're making.
So, we're gonna go ahead now
with our crawfish.
It is frozen.
So, if you don't get it fresh,
'cause of the season,
how are you accounting
for that?
I make a shellfish stock.
Got it.
And puree that directly
into the crawfish.
We want to put
more flavor in it.
Sound like
going to the dentist.
[ Whirring ]
Yeah.
We're gonna go back
to our onions.
We're gonna add
our house Creole.
Little cayenne.
Chili powder.
Salt.
We're gonna take
our white wine.
We're gonna add it to this
till it hits a low bubble.
Cream.
Crawfish puree.
Word.
Gonna add
some Parmesan cheese.
[ Whistles ]
And then throwing in
some mozzarella and provolone.
So, this
will all cook down.
Now,
how's the pasta gonna work?
We want to cook it
in stock.
Chicken stock
mixed with seafood stock.
We want to make sure
that we get as much flavor
in everything
that we're using.
Pasta's done.
Sauce is done.
And now
we're gonna plate it up.
Is this
a normal portion,
or are we feeding
a bunch of people outside?
This is
a normal portion.
We're gonna top it off
with some dried cheeses,
a little Parmesan,
Romano cheese.
Green onions, and finally,
some rough-chopped parsley.
There you go.
It's not good.
It's not great.
It's outstanding.
I get more crawfish flavor
out of this
than I do
when I eat crawfish.
It was all
from that seafood stock
that you cooked
the pasta in.
That is outrageous.
No, it really is.
It's got a nice bite,
nice acid, nice heat,
nice salt,
lots of depth.
If that's all you served,
be a line down Chinatown.
It's a favorite, and it's
probably gonna get more so.
Oh, you think?
WOMAN: It's delicious.
It's very creamy,
and it has a little spice to it.
Sauce and craw mac.
To my right here,
Alison Victoria.
Usually, you see her on DIY,
"Kitchen Crashers."
When I say
"Crawfish Mac N Cheese,"
how does this stack up?
Every bite has
the right amount of crawfish.
The sauce isn't,
like, too heavy,
and all together, it's a
beautiful palette of colors.
WOMAN: The food is delicious.
It has so much personality.
It really is
a special little place.
FIERI:
It is like I'm in N'awlins.
I mean,
it has that feeling.
Outstanding.
I mean, really, dude,
out of bounds.
FIERI: Coming up,
we're headed over to East L.A...
I like
the way this is going.
...to a funky place
totally off the beaten path...
This is
every bit fantastic.
...where Korean and Mexican
are a match made
in "Triple D" heaven.
Really is a nice fusion.
So, I'm here on the very busy
Valley Boulevard
in East Los Angeles.
Now, at any given time,
you can find some
righteous tacos in this area,
but I'm not just looking for
righteous,
I'm looking for,
like, funky fusion.
You know,
like Korean and Mexican,
and I found it right here
at Cha Cha Chili.
Spicy pork chimichanga.
Mexican and Korean food
brought together.
Can't go wrong.
Your kimchi quesadilla.
WOMAN: At first, the idea of it
seemed a bit weird,
but it's really good.
It's a great
kind of fusion of flavors.
FIERI: But confusion is
the story of this joint's past
before Chef Gavin Cha
grabbed it in 2009.
This got transformed
a few times.
House, restaurant,
house, restaurant,
restaurant, restaurant,
then we picked it up.
But for locals,
it's crystal-clear.
You can't get any tacos
like this anywhere else.
El Jefe Taco.
WOMAN: Short rib, avocado,
the chipotle chilies --
it's a good mix.
What are we into?
We're making the marinade
for the short rib.
What's the short rib
gonna be on?
The El Jefe Taco.
So, we have
the onions first.
Add a little bit of water
so it can blend.
Kiwis --
We need the enzymes
so that it breaks down
the meat a little.
Garlic, some green onion tips,
dried chili.
Drop the hammer, kid.
Now that they've blended
for a little bit,
we're gonna start with
the soy sauce.
Sugar.
Okay, next up?
The mixture.
I like
the way this is going.
Apple juice, pepper,
pineapple juice,
lemon-lime soda.
How much?
Half of it.
That's pretty good.
One of my many talents.
Okay,
so short ribs into this.
How long will
the short ribs marinate?
We do it overnight,
then we go to the grill.
Grilling outside here.
I mean, although it's in
the middle of almost a freeway.
You can't beat the mesquite.
Not bad.
Nice and hot.
Sear these off.
Now, how long will these go?
20 to 40 minutes.
Then we'll go inside and
then break it down from there.
That's right.
All right,
what are we into now, brother?
Okay, so we're gonna make
the masa for the El Jefe Taco.
We got the grilled corn.
Just cut it off.
I like the technique.
Add some water.
Lime.
All right, a little salt.
Then blend this.
Masa in the bowl
and then your mixture
with your corn.
This, to make the tortillas,
that's different.
Add some water.
Okay, now into my tortilla press
that I'll be taking home.
And that's it.
Perfect.
So, now onto the flattop.
Short rib.
Nice.
Salsa verde.
Okay.
Pieces of chipotle.
There you go.
Some avocado.
We top it off
with the Cotija cheese.
Here we go.
Mmm.
Outstanding.
The short rib is super tender.
You get all the balance
that you're looking for.
Avocado works perfectly.
Actually, the highlight,
for me, is that tortilla.
Mmm.
Ground-up corn in there,
I'm ripping that one off, man.
Excellent taco.
El Jefe Taco.
The spice from the chipotle
just makes a great combination.
Handmade corn tortilla --
it's out of this world.
MAN:
Order up. Jalapeño Bomb.
MAN #2:
It has character and flavor,
and I just like sitting out here
watching the traffic go by.
This is a street
that's well-traveled.
It is an industrial
neighborhood.
We have
some offices over there,
car wash,
some factories.
We're out
in the middle of nowhere.
FIERI:
But that's not stopping folks
from finding
their full-flavored combos.
WOMAN:
Spicy pork chimichanga.
It's like a sushi roll
mixed with a burrito.
It's really good.
We're gonna make the spicy pork
for the chimichanga.
We're making the marinade.
We're putting garlic
in it,
some roasted jalapeño,
onion,
gochugaro,
which is --
Korean dried chili powder.
That's right.
Black pepper.
Ginger.
Doctor.
Thank you.
Gochujang,
which is Korean chili paste.
Some soy sauce.
Okay, next?
Apple juice.
And pineapple juice.
Got it.
So, we blend the sucker.
We just
dropped the hammer!
Then here we have
thinly sliced pork butt.
That's right.
Marinade.
All right, so we'll let this go
for 24 hours.
Is this cooked on the flattop
or the grill?
We're doing this
on the flattop.
What are we adding now?
Tortilla,
homemade beans, cheese,
marinaded rice,
spicy pork.
Spicy mayo.
Got it.
And a little Sriracha
itself.
Exactly.
Roll this up.
Yeah, right.
Are you really gonna
fit that in there?
I'm just one man.
[ Laughs ]
And we're gonna stick it
in batter.
We're tempura-ing
the chimichanga.
Exactly.
How long's this gonna cook?
For about 12 minutes.
Chimichanga big it is.
I've had a lot of chimichangas.
I've never had one tempura-ed.
This thing is crazy.
This just turned into
a gigantic Mexican maki roll.
Cheese, spicy mayo,
Sriracha again.
[ Whistles ]
Mmm.
This is
every bit fantastic.
Tons of flavor,
little bit of heat.
But the crunch
is outrageous.
The little tempura kiss
that you give it...
That's outrageous.
Well done, my friend.
Spicy pork chimichanga.
MAN:
I like the Korean-ness of it.
I like the Mexican-ness of it.
And it just tastes good.
Mini quesadilla.
Got this great bedrock
of heat.
Did you just drop me
a "bedrock of heat" in there?
I did, man.
I went old-school.
[ Laughs ]
It's a no-brainer when it comes
to deciding to come here.
It really is
a nice fusion --
something funky,
something a little
off the beaten path.
Excellent.
FIERI: Up next in Charlotte,
North Carolina...
That's really,
really good.
...a pizzeria where
it's all in the family...
You've thrown a few pizzas
in your day.
...and straight out of Serbia?
I'm actually disappointed that
I haven't tried this before.
You know, we've all heard
the term
"Living the American dream."
Well, I'm here in Charlotte,
North Carolina,
a mile from the downtown area,
where a Serbian family
is living the American dream.
They got a funky, little joint
where they're serving up --
now, get this,
pizza and Serbian food,
just what you'd expect.
This Intermezzo Pizzeria.
[ Speaking Serbian ]
It's something way more
than a regular pizzeria.
Fricassee, order up.
It's a very, very diverse menu.
Eggplant Musaka.
Literally, I forget
I'm in Charlotte when I'm here.
This feels like
going to a Serbian home.
FIERI: It basically is,
with brothers
Djordie and Branko Avramovic
and mom Dobrila dishing it up.
Who's in charge?
Mom's charge.
Let's face it.
I know.
But it was Dad who first wanted
to open a neighborhood joint.
Was your father part
of opening this?
No,
my father passed away
a year and a half
after we came here.
FIERI: His sons
kept working on his dream,
and in 2007,
finally made it happen.
Karadjordjeva, order up.
This the place to come
for traditional food
made in a traditional way.
Piroska, order up.
The Piroska is like
a calzone but better.
It's like pizza
to the ninth degree.
FIERI: All right, man.
Okay, pizza sauce,
tomato paste, fresh tomatoes.
I'm gonna end up wearing
some of the pizza sauce.
Oh, come on.
Then add Parmesan,
salt, pepper,
parsley, oregano.
You mix this up.
How long does this
come together for flavor?
At least 24 hours.
Okay.
Then it's good to go.
Whoa!
You're dangerous with that.
Just stay away from me.
En garde.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're going to
make the...
Piroska.
...Piroska
You've thrown
a few pizzas in your day.
Nah.
Yeah.
Mozzarella cheese.
A little ricotta,
parsley-garlic mix,
mushrooms, ham.
And this is
a traditional Piroska?
Yes.
From my neck of the woods.
I like this.
And we go to the oven.
505.
505?
Yeah, 10 minutes.
Look at that thing, huh?
Sour cream goes
on top of Piroska.
Provolone cheese on top.
Pizza sauce.
This is how we serve it.
This is how we serve it?
Yep,
you've been served.
[ Laughs ]
Wow.
That's really, really good.
The yeast in the dough
really adds a nice tang.
The sour cream,
without question, is fantastic.
And then the mushrooms
and the ham.
It's dynamite.
I'm actually disappointed
that I haven't tried this
before.
You learn something new
every day. Piroska.
Piroska.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
WOMAN: Piroska.
It's like the flavor explosion
of a pizza, it's inside-out.
One of the best things
I've ever eaten.
Everything I've had here
has been excellent.
It's just a great sense
of a community.
It seems like everybody
that comes in here
has known these guys
forever.
FIERI: Even if they don't always
know what they're saying.
[ Conversing in Serbian ]
I can imagine you bring people
in for the pizza,
but they come back
for the Serbian food.
I would say
over 50% is Serbian food,
which we did not expect
at first.
Becka, order up.
When they opened up,
I learned a lot of new words.
Like musaka.
Musaka
Sarma.
Sarma is a stuffed cabbage.
Just like at home.
Tell me how we make it
in Serbia.
First,
we got to pickle it.
Okay.
So, we're gonna core it out.
We put the salt
in the hole.
Seriously?
Yeah.
This is getting interesting
right off the bat.
Add a little vinegar,
water.
How long's this gonna pickle?
Two to three weeks.
Two to three weeks?
Yes.
All right.
That's good.
Trim this back a little bit
so it rolls easier.
Yes, sir.
As soon as we get done with
these, we make the stuffing.
Yes.
Got it.
Add some oil.
Onion, carrots.
Lots of onions and carrots
in Serbian food?
Yes. Root.
They can grow in the cold.
Yes.
We add pork, beef,
and we brown everything.
We're gonna add salt,
pepper, garlic,
smoked pork loin,
short-grain rice.
Blend all this together,
cook it for a couple of minutes,
and it's ready
to stuff the cabbage.
This is gonna be good.
Gonna start with the paprika
on the bottom.
Oil.
Throw a little extra cabbage
there as a barrier.
Yep.
Take a little meat right there,
roll over nicely, tuck.
Put sideways.
Then you're gonna add
smoked ribs.
For the flavor?
Yeah.
Deglaze this
with pizza sauce and water,
and then you pour that
over the top of it.
More paprika, in the oven,
450 for one hour,
and we drop it down without
the lid about three hours.
This cooks for four hours?
Yes, sir.
Yes, Serbian.
I like that.
Wow.
I got to get you
some bread.
And you make
the bread also?
Yes, sir.
So, we take it like this?
Yes.
Mmm.
This is stuffed cabbage
with an attitude.
Tender,
a real depth of flavor.
The broth
that's coming from this...
Outstanding.
Thank you.
All right, guys, the Sarma.
MAN: With the savoriness
of the ground beef
and the pickling of the cabbage,
it's a really nice mix.
You a big
stuffed cabbage guy?
My mom used to make it
as a kid, yeah.
Sorry, Mom, but this is
actually much better.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
Beef Burek, order up.
If you come here,
you'll feel warm,
you'll feel welcomed,
and you'll have a great meal.
Home run, for sure.
I think your dad would be
so incredibly proud
of you and your brother
and your mom
for what you've done.
Got to come meet
this family.
They are living
the American dream.
Delicious.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Camera one.
Camera two.
He wins.