Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
My mouth is watering so bad
right now.
...we're getting sweet...
I'm digging this.
...savory...
Ridiculous flavor.
...and even a little saucy...
I'm halfway through the book,
and I just can't put it down.
...In Bakersfield, California.
You want to wrassle?
An old-school joint
rocking a café classic...
I've done a lot of chili
on "Triple D."
This is some of the best.
...alongside a decadent twist.
You're probably gonna
lose your mind.
Then across town...
I like it.
...a funky spot
building up their burgers...
That's a complete program.
...and putting breakfast
into dessert.
Who puts bacon in ice cream?
That's like --
Well, these guys
are a little whacked.
FIERI:
And in Phoenix, Arizona...
Oh, my goodness.
...full-flavored Mexican...
This is like Mexican
Thanksgiving in a taco.
...taking me
on a righteous ride.
That's like Mexican mole
Disneyland.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, here I am downtown
Bakersfield, California,
on a very busy street
to meet a guy that, get this,
is a third-generation coffee
shop and truck stop owner.
You don't hear that every day.
This is the 24th Street Café.
Huevos rancheros.
When you walk into it,
it's like walking into the past.
I've been coming here
for about 27 years.
Salmon dip,
share, please.
24th Street Café
is an institution.
FIERI: Because of chef and owner
Mark Huggs,
who grew up working
in his family's restaurants,
including locally renowned
Milt's Coffee Shop.
Then in 1987, he bought a diner
dating back to the '50s
and turned it into this place.
How does it keep going
if it's been here since '53?
It's all my employees.
How long
have they been here?
George -- 27 years.
Larry -- 22.
So, we're talking,
like, lifetimes.
Yeah, everybody.
MAN:
Donna and the other waitresses,
they know how I like my coffee,
how far away
to keep the mayonnaise.
And let's not forget about
the scratch-made comfort food.
Chili, please.
Chili's always a mainstay.
It's really tasty, hearty.
What are we gonna make
today?
Texas chili.
Let's get after this.
We have our top sirloin
and our chuck.
I'm gonna cube it
into strips.
This is what we grind for
all of our hamburger and chili.
Got it.
Who's this character?
This is my father.
That's the Milt?
How are you, sir?
Good to meet you.
So, Milt,
you had the truck stop.
Your kid worked for you.
Oh, yeah.
[ Laughter ]
He was a hard worker.
I was happy to see him
get out on his own.
I thought
it was a great idea.
All right, Milt.
Thanks, Dad.
So now here we are.
We got coarse ground meat.
And all we do is add our onions
and our garlic.
Okay.
So all this
is just mixed up.
Take it to the oven and brown it
at 350 for one hour.
Now we're working on the peppers
for the chili.
This is the sauce.
Got it.
So first guajillo peppers,
California.
They're my favorites.
And then the pasillas.
Garlic. Water.
And now?
Now these seep.
Then we'll take all that,
simmer it,
blend it,
run it through a strainer?
Yes.
Got it.
This is our browned meat.
Yo, it smells good enough
to get in it.
Now we're gonna add our salt,
our cayenne pepper,
chili flakes,
black pepper.
My mouth is so watering so bad
right now.
Paprika, cumin.
So we get this
nicely mixed up.
Then, can you believe it?
Go old school on it.
I do oatmeal in it.
This is gonna be
our secret.
So this is what's gonna
soak up the fat.
That's it.
It's gonna add texture.
This is a good flavor
right here.
I should probably taste this
in here.
Oh, good.
I'm halfway through the book,
and I just can't put it down.
What's up next?
Chili sauce,
and then we're gonna add
our fresh stewed tomatoes.
This is real-deal
old school.
You should wear a cowboy hat.
I should call you Hoss.
I got my boots.
How long is this gonna go
back in the oven for?
About another hour.
Hit it.
This is it.
We finish it off
with tillamook cheddar cheese.
Green onions.
Got to have it.
Fresh Spanish white onions.
If there's one thing I love
about truck stops
or counter cafés
is chili.
With a little bit of
the French fry going in there.
I mean, come on.
Mmm.
The texture of the meat
is spot-on.
Totally the right grind.
You really cooked this down.
You let all these flavors
come together.
You rendered that fat
out of the meat.
You brought it together
with the oatmeal.
Gonna eat it all?
You want to wrassle?
I've done a lot of chili
on "Triple D,"
but I will honestly tell you,
this is some of the best.
Mmm, out of bounds.
Outstanding.
It's got a little heat to it.
Not greasy on the top.
Absolutely you can tell
they're making it from scratch.
In the world of chili,
how do you rate that?
This is top 10.
He really has a great menu.
WOMAN: Chicken piccata.
FIERI:
Which can be eaten up at --
what you don't see too much
anymore -- good,
old-fashioned counter space.
When you sit at the counter,
there's always something to do.
People are talking.
A waitress comes by.
Just the ambiance of a true café
is a real landmark.
All right, so if you could take
something as average as chili
and make it that fantastic,
when we come back,
we're gonna make pancakes.
Not just any pancakes.
Pumpkin pancakes.
My taste buds have never tasted
pancakes this good.
Pumpkin pancakes,
"Triple D" in Bakersfield.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Gonna take me that long
to eat the chili.
Welcome back.
We're at the 24th Street Café
here in Bakersfield, California.
I just had a bowl of chili.
Well, it was kind of like
the bowl of chilis
of bowl of chilis.
Outstanding.
So, I agreed that, if the chili
was that fantastic,
I will try pancakes.
I heard that
the pumpkin pancakes are
[Whistles]
out of this world.
They are.
They're just light, fluffy,
melt-in-your-mouth yumminess.
Pumpkin pancakes,
double share, please.
The pumpkin pancakes
are my guilty pleasure.
Got a great cinnamon,
pumpkin flavor.
And then you've got that
pecan brown sugar butter
that is unbelievable.
This is more like
pumpkin pie.
I'll take it.
First ground pumpkin.
Nutmeg, cinnamon, vanilla,
salt, brown sugar.
Condensed milk.
So this is from scratch?
Yes.
Whole milk.
In Bakersfield, they still
have milk in the glass jars.
Milk in a jar.
Eggs.
And a little oil.
How long have the pumpkin
pancakes been on the menu?
Ooh, 20 years, at least.
So we just mix this,
and then we mix the dry mixture.
All-purpose flour,
baking powder, salt, and sugar.
A little sugar.
So just like baking a cake.
Wet mix, dry mix.
You add it to it.
All right, and then that's gonna
get served with what?
Pecan butter.
Pecan butter?
Boy, where you from?
Bakersfield.
Okay,
so whipped butter.
Pecans, brown sugar,
pure vanilla extract,
cinnamon, and clove.
I love it.
All right, now we're gonna
cook the pancakes?
Yes.
There you go.
Now,
because my friend Kat,
who is the producer
here of "Triple D,"
is such a fan of pumpkin
pancakes, so I'm doing this.
This is all for Kat.
Mmm.
That's hot
pumpkin cheesecake.
Not as heavy and dense.
The cakes are nice and light.
It's actually the pecan butter
that really ties it all in.
Getting a little of that
saltiness and the crunchiness
in the nuts.
Anybody that's a pancake fan,
anybody that's a pumpkin fan --
If you're a fan of both, you're
probably gonna lose your mind.
WOMAN:
It's like jamming Thanksgiving
pumpkin pie year-round
in your mouth.
MAN: Pancakes are big,
and they're fluffy,
and you better be hungry
if you order them.
Is this
a step back in time?
Yeah.
It's the kind of restaurant,
when you move away
and you come back in town
and you want your favorite meal,
this is where you come to.
This is my "Cheers" bar.
I would much rather come to Café
than go any place else.
FIERI:
This is the kind of place
that you wish
was right down the street
from your house.
Diamond, baby.
There you go.
It's a diamond.
FIERI: Coming up,
we're sticking to Bakersfield...
I'm feeling encouragement.
...to see if a joint
has what it takes...
I'm almost ready to try
the peanut butter crunch burger.
...to conquer
one of my burger blues.
I never thought
it would happen.
So, I'm here
off the West Side Parkway
right by some railroad tracks
in an industrial park
in Bakersfield, California.
Sounds exciting, I know,
but hang on, this is a good one.
I'm here to check out a joint
where a husband-and-wife team
decided to open up
an ice cream shop/restaurant/
coffee bar
that serves wine and craft beer.
Mm, that's a mouthful.
And this is Moo Creamery.
YOSHIMURA: Chilaquiles.
MAN:
The second you open the door,
you're just greeted
by good vibes.
WOMAN:
I think people don't know that
it's gonna be as delicious
as it is, but it is.
It's good.
Bacon-fried rice.
You keep driving, like,
"Where is it?"
I thought I was lost.
Like, GPS is lying to me.
And then you get here,
and it's awesome.
FIERI: This hidden gem
belongs to Jessica Pounds
and Richard Yoshimura,
who said "I do" to more than
just this joint in 2008.
How many months had you
been married before
you opened the Moo?
Three months.
That has got to be
some bond.
This place is known for the
burgers and the ice cream.
Peanut butter crunch
burger.
They're juicy, and everything
smooshes together.
And you just get a perfect bite.
So, what are we gonna make?
Bacon jam for the peanut butter
crunch burger.
I had a peanut butter burger
one time.
I absolutely don't enjoy that
at all.
[ Laughter ]
Good luck.
We're gonna start off
by slicing up some bacon here.
Let it render down.
Get nice, crunchy bacon?
Yes. And we'll leave
some of the fat in there
and cook off
the rest of this stuff.
Throwing the onions in.
Salt and pepper.
Garlic.
Brown sugar.
Every time you dump something
in, I will remove some bacon.
[ Laughs ]
Maple syrup, coffee.
And a little ACV.
Apple cider vinegar.
I like it.
And then we're gonna throw in
the bacon.
That's all cooked down.
What's next?
We're gonna put it
in the food processor.
Really jam it up.
Exactly.
Now we're gonna make
the pepper relish.
All this is going
for one item on the menu?
Yes.
He's got a lot of time
on his hands.
Layers.
Was that
a little break dance?
Throw some music to that,
please.
Now I'm gonna add the oil,
some shallots,
salt, pepper, garlic.
I like the copious amounts
of garlic that are used.
Serrano chili.
I always love heat
on my peanut butter burger.
And we're adding
the chopped red peppers.
Apple cider vinegar.
Sugar.
This'll cook down
for about 45 minutes.
I'm feeling encouragement,
from the bacon jam
to the relish.
I'm almost ready to try the
peanut butter crunch burger.
Gonna start with the bacon jam
on that homemade brioche bun.
Whoa.
And on the top bun,
we're gonna put on homemade
peanut butter, pepper relish.
Patty with two slices
of sharp cheddar.
Okay.
We have a little arugula with
a honey chipotle vinaigrette.
And here's a crunch element --
homemade potato chips.
Gonna put to put chips
on top of it.
Yeah.
You can do it.
I never thought
it would happen.
If you're gonna call it
a peanut butter crunch burger,
you can't just make it
a one-themed experience.
It's really got to have a lot
coming on with it.
With all of the acid and all
of the creative ingredients
that you put on here,
that's a complete program.
Nicely done, my friend.
Thank you very much.
This I would definitely eat
again.
MAN:
It's like a PBJ but a burger.
It's pretty crazy,
and I like it.
The potato chips are crunchy.
The peanut butter is salty.
Perfectly-cooked burger.
FIERI:
Sure, the burgers are a hit,
but this joint's called
Moo Creamery for a reason.
You want to come in,
have an ice cream sundae,
we got something
for everybody.
Two scoops bacon love.
Who puts bacon in ice cream?
That's like --
Well, these guys
are a little whacked here.
Exactly.
That's why it's special.
"Exactly."
WOMAN:
You would think that with bacon,
it's like breakfast,
but everything about it
is dessert.
[ Deep voice ] Luke, we're
making bacon love ice cream.
[ Laughter ]
We're gonna put in the cream,
milk, brown sugar.
Whisk that up.
Which way do you do it?
This way.
Maple syrup,
vanilla extract.
Salt.
Got it.
So this is the base.
Now we're gonna caramelize
some bacon again.
Now onto the sheet tray,
let it cool.
Then the big chill.
So here we are
in the deep freeze.
How cold is it in here?
40.
All right, hit it.
So, we're gonna put that
maple brown sugar base
right into our batch freezer,
turn it on.
This takes
about eight minutes.
So now we're ready
to extract.
When do we start
sprinkling the bacon?
You can do it right now.
I'm digging this.
So if you wanted to serve it
gelato style, we're ready to go.
We're ready to go.
Wow.
You know what plays off this
so well is that maple syrup.
That accentuates the bacon
flavor right off the bat.
Super creamy.
Out of the 10 scoops
I've already had,
I've got bacon
every single time.
That's the love
right there.
You the man.
Great job, dude.
I'm gonna tell ya,
you have delivered
how much you said
you were gonna do.
Outstanding.
The ice cream is so smooth,
so creamy.
This is the best ice cream
in the world.
So I thought
the perfect people
to ask what they thought
of Moo Creamery
would be my management team
from the Johnny Garlic's
here in Bakersfield.
They get everything locally
here,
giving right back
to the community.
I love the originality.
Now, you worked here.
And six years later,
it's cracking,
just as it was day one.
This place is definitely
the X on the treasure map.
I like to see that young people
like yourselves
are jumping in there,
trying to make this happen,
doing it as a couple.
That's why
they're so successful.
Great place, you guys.
FIERI:
Up next in Phoenix, Arizona...
Oh, that's so good.
...the Mexican spot
tricking out tortillas...
That's why it says
gourmet taco shop out front.
...and taking mole to the max.
I would stand with that pot
of mole on the side of the road
and serve it to people
in their hands.
So, I'm here
in Phoenix, Arizona,
in the barrio of Barrio Café.
You remember, Chef Silvana --
real-deal Mexican food.
I'm about two blocks away
to check out
another real-deal joint.
This time,
they serve it all in a taco.
This is La Santisima.
I've never had Mexican food
like this.
Ready.
This is real Mexican food.
When someone genuinely
puts their soul into it,
you can taste
a little bit of that.
FIERI: Here, the soul comes from
owner Christina Guzman,
a Mexican immigrant
who traded in the furniture biz
for family recipes in 2010.
You take all the different
specialties of Mexico
and put it in a taco.
That's why it says
gourmet taco shop out front.
Santisima, what does that mean,
Santisima?
The Santisima is -- It comes
from the Day of the Dead.
It's a big celebration
in Mexico.
No, I know it, yeah.
They just entice you
with ingredients that they use.
The nagada tacos
has a little bit of fruit in it.
WOMAN:
It symbolizes the flag.
You have your white, your red,
and your green.
So, this is like
a pretty important dish.
It's really important, like,
in Independence Day.
All right,
so let's get started.
Olive oil with onion.
Some garlic.
Ground beef, ground pork.
It's kind of like
piccadillo.
It's like piccadillo,
okay.
We add the raisins, salt,
pepper -- that's it.
Now we have to do the mix
of the fruit.
Olive oil.
Garlic.
We have onion.
Pears?
Pears, yes.
In Mexican food?
Of course.
Apple, prunes.
I'm just gonna keep
all the prune jokes to myself.
Cinnamon.
Add tomatoes.
And salt and pepper
on this?
A little bit, yeah.
We're gonna do the stuffing.
So, we start with the mix.
We're gonna mix it right now
with the fruit mix that we did.
Then we're gonna heat
a little bit of peppers.
Roasted?
Mm-hmm.
Got it.
What's in the sauce?
Milk, walnuts, cherry,
goat cheese,
and Mexican cinnamon.
Then we add some pepper,
pomegranate.
The color
of the Mexican flag.
Yeah.
Oh, my goodness.
It's rich, it's creamy, complex,
has a lot of texture.
This is like Mexican
Thanksgiving in a taco.
A little bit of sweet
and a little bit
of a spiciness, as well.
Pomegranate seeds on it
give it a little bit of crunch.
It's just something
you can't get
in all these other
Mexican restaurants.
FIERI:
Same goes for the mega salsa bar
topping things off.
You can always tell
they're made fresh.
What's your favorite one?
The peanut one.
FIERI:
And another saucy favorite?
FIERI: Holy mole.
Let's talk about mole.
Mole, yeah.
It's with chicken.
Start with olive oil,
cascabel.
Cherry peppers, got it.
The next one is the ancho.
The ancho.
Guajillo.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Put the garlic, and then
we're gonna do the nut mix.
Good,
before I eat 'em all.
Olive oil, peanuts,
almonds, pecans.
Lots of nuts.
The walnut.
The sesame seed.
All the stems and seeds
from the peppers, oil.
That good?
Yeah.
Toasted all the nut mixture.
Next, the tomatillos
and the tomatoes and the onions.
Onions and garlic.
We are up to like 40 ingredients
on this.
Add some chicken broth.
Then you have --
Spice mix.
Cinnamon, marjoram.
Oregano.
Anise.
Cloves, thyme,
black pepper.
What is this?
That's chocolate
from Oaxaca.
All of 'em?
Yeah.
The cinnamon sticks.
Avocado leaves, just a little
bread to tighten it up.
More chicken broth.
And how long is this
gonna cook together?
10, 15 minutes.
And then
we're gonna puree it?
Yeah.
Let it rest in the fridge
three days.
We've been here for like a week
trying to get this done.
We've got our paste.
Now we're gonna cook the sauce
a second time,
and this is what we're gonna put
with the chicken
to make the taco.
Yeah.
Start with the chicken broth,
tomato puree,
and chocolate.
Now we add
some of the mole base.
Such a process.
We add the chicken base.
The sauce is ready.
Now the chicken thighs.
This will bring a lot of the
richness back to the bird.
Plate it.
[ Whistles ]
I'm just one man.
You look hungry.
We add some onion...
Some sesame seeds.
There you go.
Oh, my gosh.
You get a bit
of the sweetness.
You get spice.
You get depth.
There's so many facets.
Look at that chicken.
Tender
and ridiculous flavor.
Oh, that is so good.
I've had some great mole before.
That's one of the best ever.
Mmm, it's like Mexican mole
Disneyland.
But it's not a small world.
That's a big world of flavor.
Mole taco.
MAN: It's so rich.
It just has enough
of that sweetness,
and then the chicken
is cooked just perfectly.
I love the mole, and it really
reminds me of my grandma's.
I would stand with that pot
of mole on the side of the road
and serve it to people
in their hands.
Nice job.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Find the...
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]