Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Get after that!
...we're racing through
Charlotte, North Carolina...
Put your seatbelt on.
You might need it.
...with NASCAR driver
Clint Bowyer along for the ride.
How did you just drop the NASCAR
right into my cooking show?
First...
I'll take another one
of those.
...a reborn "Triple D"
favorite...
Whaa!
...going full-throttle
with their burgers.
You're attacking this thing.
It's like a coyote
got ahold of it.
Then...
[ Chuckles ]
...a crazy go-kart pit stop...
Is this the "drive" part of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"?
...dishing out
first-place fixings.
There's nothing I would change
about the sandwich.
And we're crossing
the finish line...
What did you say?!
...at a funky food truck...
That's a new one.
...where Clint's buckling up
for a culinary adventure.
[ Chuckles ]
Uh...
I'm gonna try this.
Okay.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
So, I'm cruising around here
in the Charlotte Motor Speedway.
I think I might be lost,
but I'm looking for my buddy
Clint Bowyer.
What's up, Bowyer?
City boy!
[ Laughs ]
Finally at a racetrack.
I'll tell you what.
I got a challenge for you.
Fastest lap
around Charlotte Motor Speedway,
you either drive my racecar
for a day,
or I get to host "Triple D."
No problem.
[ Tires squeal ]
You're up.
[ Tires screech ]
I smoked you.
[ Laughs ]
That wasn't even close.
Well, no kidding.
I smoked you.
You're killing me.
Smoked you.
I'll tell you what. This is how
we're gonna settle this.
You go ahead
and make some laps in my car,
but I am hosting "Triple D,"
and I am not bleaching my hair.
Get in. Let's go to
downtown Charlotte.
Put your seatbelt on.
You might need it.
[ Bell rings ]
You drive too fast.
You're just mad
'cause you lost.
I am mad 'cause I lost.
So, we're on the west side
of Charlotte, North Carolina.
Now,
you remember the Penguin?
Everybody
remembers the Penguin.
Well, it closed,
but the guy, Greg,
opened up a new joint over here
on the west side.
And you know what?
This is
Pinky's Westside Grill.
Redneck turf and surf up.
The people, the energy, the food
is good.
Whoo!
MAN: Love it.
I'm here about
three or four times a week.
This used to be an old garage
that worked on Volkswagens.
That's why there's a Volkswagen
on the roof.
FIERI:
This old garage switched gears
from cars to cooking in 2010
when chef and owner Greg Auten
cruised over
from a legendary local spot.
It was
about eight years ago
that we met you
at the Penguin
in a funky little joint
in a great time.
That place has closed.
Things have changed.
To see how you reopened,
it's bigger, it's badder,
it's faster than it was.
It's everything from
"Oh, I just want a salad"
or a fat hamburger
with everything on it.
AUTEN:
Triple "G" in the window.
Triple "G" has three patties.
It's got slaw, chili, mustard,
and American cheese.
And why do you call it
the Triple "G" burger?
Because it was Triple "G"
Volkswagen repair.
See, I thought when you called
this the Triple "G" burger
it was "Guy's Grocery Games."
Even in Charlotte,
it's got to be about Guy.
[ Laughs ] All right.
What do you got, buddy?
We are making our house-made
chili for the Triple "G" burger.
Got it.
80/20 ground beef.
Water going in.
Yellow onion.
Fresh garlic.
Lot of garlic.
That's a good thing.
Chili powder.
Black pepper.
Seasoning salt.
Coriander.
Hot sauce. Cumin.
Okay, so this all cooks down.
Then you add the tomato paste.
Cook it up,
and this will be the chili
that's going on top
of the Triple "G" burger.
Let's cook.
Are you just gonna get
right into the cooking
part of this right now?
Yes. Ready to cook.
This is it --
the Triple "G" burger.
This is what
we've been waiting for, huh?
This is what this place
was founded on.
Three 5-ounce patties.
Stack 'em up, baby.
Stack 'em and go.
Oh, my.
We've got the pound of meat,
three pieces of cheese,
house Southern slaw,
mustard, chopped onions.
And then the chili.
Put this on top.
I want to see you do this.
I don't know how to do this.
Here we go.
[ Laughs ]
Get after that!
Greg, I'm telling you,
it's fantastic.
You're attacking this thing.
It's like a coyote
got ahold of it.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN: Triple "G," sir.
MAN: It's a sloppy piece
of equipment,
but it's delicious and filling.
Shrimp tacos up.
Just great food,
great atmosphere.
And it's just a wonderful energy
that's here.
Mmm.
WOMAN: Greg brings up things
that you would think, "What?!"
And when you taste it,
it's just fantastic.
Corn dog shrimp up.
Corn dog shrimp is delicious.
WOMAN:
The corn dog batter is sweet,
and then the shrimp tend to be
a little bit salty.
It's just good.
FIERI: Okay,
what are we making next?
We are making the batter
for the corn dog shrimp.
Dipsy Dog corn dog mix.
That's very old school.
A lot of fairs and circuses
and stuff like that use it.
We're gonna go in
with the water.
Then we're gonna jump on it
with a whisk.
All right, so, you see how nice
and creamy that is?
So it'll really coat
to that shrimp.
Here we go.
21-25 shrimp.
Grab them by the tail.
By the tail.
Dunk them in.
Okay.
Got to set them in there
nice and easy.
Float them a bit.
Set it in.
And let it got.
That's so it doesn't
just sink to the bottom.
Bam!
There you go.
Whaa!
Corn dog shrimp
are ready to go.
Perfect them babies are.
Pretty proud of yourself
on these, aren't you?
Yes.
Get in after it.
Oh, yeah.
They're so good.
It tastes like a corn dog --
sweet, crunchy batter.
Straight from the fair.
Not salty.
The corn dog shrimp
is something I've never had,
and I'll be back to Pinky's
weekly because they're so good.
WOMAN: Corn dog shrimp.
The breading they use on there
with the shrimp inside,
it's extra sweet.
It's always fresh shrimp.
It's great stuff.
FIERI:
So, here we are.
We're hanging out at Pinky's
in Charlotte, North Carolina.
So, when we come back,
we're gonna make --
What are we making?
The Asian pork burger.
It was the perfect burger.
It was just right.
Asian pork burger.
See you in a little bit.
Welcome back.
We're at Pinky's.
FIERI:
My good buddy Greg -- You saw
him at the Penguin years ago,
and, of course,
you know this cat Clint Bowyer.
We've already dug into
the triple-decker,
and now we're ready to roll
with a different kind of burger.
Asian pork burger up.
The Asian pork burger is sweet,
tangy. It's delicious.
What are we making?
Korean barbecue sauce
for the Asian pork burger.
We're going in
with soy sauce.
Sesame oil.
You have that in the South.
Black pepper.
Fresh garlic.
Rice wine vinegar.
Fresh ginger.
One Granny Smith apple.
That's the key
right there.
Sriracha sauce.
I don't know.
That could be it right there.
Brown sugar.
Then we're gonna thicken it
with a cornstarch slurry.
So, this cooks down.
You hold that as the sauce
that goes to the burger?
Mm-hmm.
And now we're into
the pork burger itself.
Yep. We're gonna go in
with fresh ground pork.
We have cilantro, garlic,
green onions,
rice wine vinegar,
five-spice powder,
sesame oil, dried mint,
Sriracha sauce.
Big on Sriracha.
Sriracha's good stuff, man.
Great.
Sambal chili paste.
Red curry paste.
We basically have everything but
the kitchen sink in this one.
Yes.
Fresh ginger.
Fish sauce.
That's actually an adjustment
on a racecar. You know that?
What? Fish sauce?
No, no. Everything
but the kitchen sink.
It means --
You're all over the tracks.
See? He knows.
Chili flakes.
Curry powder.
Lime juice and mirin rice wine.
All right.
We're just going hands in.
All right. Let these cook up,
put a nice little crust on them.
Yep.
Little bit of the glaze.
A cilantro honey slaw.
Okay.
Look how good it is!
I just want to show you guys
something --
my first bite
and Bowyer's first bite.
Look at his fuel tank
versus mine.
You know, you always wonder
how these restaurants
get on this show.
You don't wonder anymore
if you try that.
The balance of the flavors,
crunch of the slaw,
really nice bun, by the way.
When the sauce kicks in,
that's the best.
Real deal, man.
Damn right.
Well done.
I'll take another one of those.
Asian pork burger.
It's a nice blend of pork
with a hint of spice,
and it's nice and juicy.
This is Cassi and Marcus Smith,
and my buddy Marcus here
is the president
of Charlotte Motor Speedway.
We love Pinky's, and, I mean,
this burger is unbelievable.
Did you feel the flavor?
Oh!
I mean,
this is Flavortown.
I love this.
Ding Dong Chicken up.
All the food is right on.
It's, all around,
a good experience.
I have a cousin named Pinky,
and his real name is Greg,
so Pinky, Greg --
I mean, this was meant to be.
All right.
I'm driving to the next place.
You're not driving.
I'm driving.
Coming up...
Wow.
...we're cruising
to a food-and-fun combo...
That's just
what I was thinking.
...where Clint's trying his hand
in the kitchen...
I got it. Let me know
if you need anything.
...and I have to race
against a pro.
I treat you good
in the kitchen.
You don't go sending me
in the wall.
So, I've come all the way
to Charlotte, North Carolina,
to visit you, and you bring me
to an indoor go-kart track?
That's right.
We race in Charlotte.
Is this the "drive" part of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"?
Oh, we're gonna drive,
all right,
but let me tell you
something.
It ain't just about
go-karts here.
This is some of the best eats
in Charlotte,
and it's right here
at the Pit Road Bar & Grill.
Moon Pie sliders.
The menu at Pit Road
is out of this world.
Pimento cheeseburger.
You wouldn't expect to
find a place like this
inside a go-kart track.
The food is amazing.
Dry-rub wings.
This is a perfect situation
for us to be in in Charlotte.
FIERI:
Fueled by co-owners and in-laws
Fred Ogrim, Clay Robinson,
and Ed Bradford,
who wanted to build
a high-octane menu.
We wanted good food
for people to come and enjoy.
Real deal.
Not just coming to race
but come here to eat.
FIERI: So in 2013,
they signed up Charlotte native
and long-time kitchen vet
Donnie Simmons.
Redneck taters -- table 22.
They are risk-takers
with their flavors.
WOMAN: The Concord.
There really isn't another
place in Charlotte
to get this sandwich.
MAN: It's a fillet. They've got
a fig paste of some sort
they put on the bottom.
It's magical.
All right.
You get after it, Chef.
You like fillet?
Oh, yeah.
Who doesn't like the fillet?
So, what's in the marinade here,
boss?
SIMMONS: Marsala.
Marsala -- Not something
I expect to find at a racetrack.
Oil. Kosher salt.
Ground black pepper.
Okay.
Whisk it up a little bit.
So, we're gonna let this
marinade go for how long?
24 hours.
All right. We're gonna make
this fig compote jam?
Fig preserves.
This I got to see.
Do you eat a lot of figs?
No.
Try it. Good.
Really?
Good for you.
Man, they are good.
Let's get into this.
Apple cider vinegar.
Little acid
to cut all that sweet.
H2O.
A little sugar.
A little sugar?
That's the race fuel.
Cayenne pepper.
Coriander, ground.
Kosher salt.
Okay. How long we gonna
let this cook down?
Three hours.
You want to have Clint
just sit here and watch that
for three hours?
Sure.
I got it.
Let me know
if you need anything.
Figs are about ready,
buddy.
All right. Where are we at?
We use the immersion blender,
mix it up.
Oh, yeah.
This is awesome.
Nice.
All right.
Let's make the sandwich.
Little garlic.
Meat. Marsala.
Fire is key.
Let it cook
for about six minutes.
[ Whistles ]
Boy, it looks good, baby.
Grill our ciabatta bread.
Little of
the North Carolina figs.
[ Whistles ]
Plentiful supply there,
buddy.
Steak.
[ Chuckles ]
Little blue cheese.
Now to the pizza oven?
Two minutes
at 500 degrees.
Word.
The fig is something
I've never had.
The fillet is phenomenal.
The cheese is the ultimate.
Love you toast the bun
to death.
You really put some crunch
to it.
I'm a big fan of this contrast
between that fig jam
and that blue cheese.
It's money.
Concord.
It's really a blend
of all the flavors.
It just opens up your palate.
You get a world-class meal
and go and do some hard racing.
Can we race now?
Absolutely.
FIERI: Trust me, Clint's
been waiting for this all day.
Are you ready?
Be nice.
Come on, buttercup.
No, listen.
Come on, princess.
I treat you good
in the kitchen.
You don't go sending me
in the wall.
[ Tires squealing ]
MAN: When you're done racing,
you're tired, you're hungry,
you come in here
and have an excellent meal.
Hot Lap sandwich.
Thank you.
Awesome sandwich.
WOMAN:
It's got a little bit of kick
with their jalapeño crema
that they have in there.
It's perfect.
What are we into brother?
A Hot Lap sandwich.
We're gonna make
a little chicken marinade.
Okay.
Start with
Bloody Mary seasoning.
Kosher salt. Cumin.
Chicken base.
Fresh garlic.
Extra Worcestershire.
Extra.
Chipotles in adobo.
Yep.
Little spice there.
Mix it up.
I got this.
Let's try it out.
Oh, yeah.
I'd like a Bloody Mary
made out of that.
Yeah, no doubt.
I'm gonna put the chicken
in there,
let it marinate overnight.
Wow.
So, this marinates for a day.
Now...
Fresh lime juice.
Little blackening seasoning.
Right on top?
Right on top.
[ Whistles ]
Little taco seasoning.
That's just
what I was thinking.
Fresh-squeezed lime juice.
And how long
is this gonna bake off for?
1 hour 15 minutes.
350 degrees.
Lot of work getting
this good food out, huh?
No doubt.
While this is cooking,
let's make
the jalapeño cilantro crema.
We're gonna let Chef Bowyer
jump in on this one.
All right.
We have mayonnaise.
Sour cream.
Olive oil.
Yep.
Pennzoil.
Little garlic.
Salt, pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Onion powder.
Fresh jalapeños.
Okay.
Seeds in there.
You get a little --
Yep. Little heat.
Fresh cilantro,
stems and all.
Limes.
Nicely done.
Mix that up.
He's on his parade lap
right now.
Normally it's just --
Once he gets that pedal
down on the wood,
it's just -- That's it.
All right,
so you let this cool down.
Now you can shred it by hand.
Wow.
That is gonna be one tangy,
rich sandwich.
Little mozz.
SIMMONS:
Little mozzarella.
Two minutes in the oven,
500 degrees.
Got it.
Put a little of the crema --
nice amount.
Fresh cilantro.
All righty.
This is gonna be
a little bit spicy.
It's good, though.
I like the horsepower behind it.
How did you just drop the NASCAR
right into my cooking show?
That Bloody Mary right in there
put a ton of flavor into it.
The crema is what really
ties it all together.
I like the little fresh
herbaceous note
from the cilantro.
There's nothing I would change
about the sandwich.
Hot Lap.
The chicken with the Bloody Mary
mix is just -- It's amazing.
MAN:
The jalapeño crema sauce on it
adds a little extra bite.
It's delicious.
To be able to come in here
and get this kind of food,
this caliber of food
is awesome.
Pork shanks, Concord,
table two.
MAN: If you make it
in the front door,
you'll walk out
wanting to come back.
Nice job, man. You've got
a fantastic setup in here.
I've never had any kind of food
like this at a go-kart track.
What a pleasure.
Thank you.
Up next, we're tracking down
a food truck...
You find The Tin Kitchen,
you're on the right track.
You'll find Clint Bowyer.
FIERI: ...where their left turn
with the menu...
This variety that I've had today
is pretty wild.
FIERI: ...takes you right down
the road to Flavortown.
Do you need another one?
[ Muffled ] I didn't like it.
Well, Guy, thanks for taking me
back to the track,
but I thought we were gonna hit
another "Triple D" joint.
We are. It's right here, Clint.
This is The Tin Kitchen.
Pork belly tacos.
You're gonna find something
you won't find anywhere else.
Restaurant-quality food
without all the fuss.
Hot pan, hot pan.
MAN: If you have a good chef
that knows what he's doing
he can put the flavors together,
and he can serve it
from anywhere.
FIERI: David Stuck has been
proving that since 2011
when he picked up this rig and
took his kitchen to the street.
What is the type of food that
you make? What's the specialty?
Got a little bit of everything
going on.
[ Engines roaring ]
Tacos, quesadillas,
and sliders.
What did you say?!
[ Engine revs ]
Is it always this loud?
You're at a racetrack!
Of course it is.
His imagination is amazing
to be able to come up
with all these dishes.
Two buffalo cauliflower sliders
are up.
MAN: It's a vegetarian dish.
I thought I might miss the meat,
but I don't.
It's delicious. It's perfect.
What are we gonna make first?
Buffalo cauliflower sliders.
[ Laughs ]
Uh...
I'm gonna try this.
Okay.
We're gonna start with
the celery root slaw.
Green cabbage.
A little bit
of celery root.
That's a new one.
Red onions.
Little parsley.
And some shaved celery.
Got our celery seed aioli.
This will be the base
for the sandwich.
Oh!
That's good slaw.
It's that celery root.
Nice call.
Now time
for the cauliflower steak.
He's gonna cut the center
out of this cauliflower.
Little olive oil,
salt, and pepper.
Correct.
Onto that hot plancha.
And how are we serving this?
On a slider?
On a slider
with blue cheese.
Little buffalo sauce.
And the slaw.
And we're gonna take
the finished steaks,
stack them up nice
for you.
And then just a little bit
of crumbled blue cheese.
And then the scallions.
That's all she wrote.
So, I got to warn you.
It's a little messy.
No...
This is good -- really good.
What are you tasting?
Great heat
from the cauliflower.
Nice and tender, not mushy.
Love the char.
The celery root slaw
got awesome texture.
I mean, the texture's
just fantastic.
That's more cauliflower
than you've eaten
since I've known you.
[ Laughs ]
In my life.
Good.
Thanks, brother.
Real good.
I got this.
All right. Let's see this.
What do you think?
It's amazing.
It's such a unique idea,
I had to try it.
It's my favorite.
It's perfectly tangy,
crunchy, and spicy.
Like, you forget
you're eating a vegetable.
FIERI:
And folks are willing to chase
this guy all over town for it.
He's very easy to find.
They're very prevalent
on Facebook, Twitter.
He's definitely one of the best.
I like their gourmet approach
to the taco.
FIERI: Like this one,
straight out of India.
Two chana masala tacos.
I would never think to put
chana masala inside of a taco.
It's amazing.
All right.
What are we making next?
We're gonna do
a chana masala dish
over apricot and Medjool date
couscous.
Never heard of that,
either.
Right over the top.
All right, Dave.
Let's get started.
Israeli couscous.
So, this will be the base.
Kind of like pasta balls.
Toasted almond slivers
here.
Smoked tomatoes.
Little bit of apricots here.
The Medjool date.
Exactly.
Cilantro.
Fresh-squeezed lemon juice.
Then we're just gonna
mix this here up.
So, next, we're gonna do
the chana masala.
The chana masala.
We're gonna start
with olive oil.
Onions --
This is traditional mirepoix.
Carrots and celery,
as well.
So, this is about as traditional
as it comes.
Exactly. A little garlic.
Smelling good already.
Coriander next,
curry powder.
Now let that toast up
a little bit.
Go in with our chickpeas.
Or garbanzo bean.
Not your favorite?
Not the best bean.
[ Laughs ]
Not the best bean
in the world.
He just chucked it
out the door.
Coconut milk first.
Gonna get some lime
in there.
And then we'll just
mix that up.
We're gonna hit it
with a little salt and pepper
and let it
all come together.
So, let this reduce
about 20 or 30 minutes,
and then we eat some tacos.
Exactly.
Just get a little bit of this
couscous down in the base.
That chana masala
right over the top.
Right on the top?
Yes, sir.
We're gonna give it
this little goat cheese
and then
a little bit of scallions.
I'm telling you,
you've done your homework,
and this is awesome.
I'm getting a lot of that great
rich flavor coming through
from the coconut milk,
and, all of a sudden,
I just got a little bit
of the slivered almond,
and then I just got a little bit
of the tang of the apricot
come through.
This is really,
really good.
Well, I'm glad you like it.
That's for sure.
Oh!
Do you need another one?
[ Muffled ]
I didn't like it.
[ Laughter ]
Two chana masalas.
This just has the right touch
of curry seasoning in it.
MAN: All the flavors
just come together.
They never miss a beat.
This variety that I've had today
is pretty wild.
Honestly,
I would have never tried this
had I not been on this show
and had this opportunity.
You find The Tin Kitchen,
you're on the right track.
You'll find Clint Bowyer.
MAN: Some of the best food
you'll have anywhere,
whether it's out of a truck
or out of
a brick-and-mortar restaurant.
Hands down, the best in town.
So, that's it
for this special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"
here in Charlotte,
North Carolina,
but don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Hey, Guy!
Guy! Clint Bowyer
just stole The Tin Kitchen!
It's happened to me.
Don't worry about it.
He won't bring it back.
You got to coach me here,
buddy.
You're doing great.
You're doing good. Sure.
He will walk us off the cliff
if you let him.
Oh, that's --
that's hilarious.
It's not funny, Guy!
Caution on the speedway.