Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Simmer down!
...we're digging
into some fresh fish...
Let's get into it.
...Irish pub grub...
[ Groans ]
...and meaty feet.
I've enjoyed all the parts
of the pig now, I think.
In Syracuse, New York...
This is the Irish pub
you've been training for!
...doing a turn
on the reuben...
Stack 'em up
like cannonballs.
Cannonballs.
...and an Irish mix
on the meatloaf.
I'm illegally rippin'
that one off.
Then an eclectic
barbecue place...
You put a lot of yourself
in this.
...killing it
with their turf and surf.
You couldn't make that
any better.
And in Atlantic City,
New Jersey...
You're just loading it up,
aren't you?
...a down-home
soul-food spot...
Guess what we're gonna
put in next.
...handing out the hoof.
Gonna have some pigs' feet
on "Triple D."
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
I'm here in downtown
Syracuse, New York,
to check out a real-deal
Irish pub --
not one of those joints
that puts an Irish beer sign
up on the wall
and serves a little
corned beef and cabbage.
I'm talking the real-deal,
the real-deal,
where the owner,
he was born in Dublin, Ireland!
This is the Irish pub
you've been training for!
Welcome to Kitty Hoynes.
Irish breakfast up.
It's top-of-the-line pub food.
You can get anything
from fish and chips,
filets and steaks and lobster.
Shepherd's pie up.
-Been to Ireland?
-Yes. Yes.
-We have been.
-So this is what it feels like?
-Yeah.
-It's an Irish bar.
GUY: No doubt,
and owner David Hoyne
has got the accent to prove it.
[ Irish accent ] Thank you
for coming this evening.
He brought his brogue
to his wife's hometown in '99,
opened up this joint,
and named it after his mom.
Who is -- does he work
here with you?
-Sometimes.
-She's the boss.
She picked up a little
bit of your accent.
A little bit.
So tell me
what a real Irish pub is.
The food, which is
a very special part of this.
And you have to have
a mighty craic in it.
And crack is all about
having the fun.
So seriously, that's the term --
it's gotta have a lot of
craic in it?
Yep -- c-r-a-i-c.
When you have the music,
you have people conversing,
having a good time.
That is when it's
a real Irish pub.
GUY: And the chef
behind the craicin' menu...
Order up.
...is Boston-import
Damien Brownlow,
who's taking Irish pub grub
to a whole other level,
like this deep-fried
spin on the Reuben.
And there's your
Reuben Fritters.
MAN: It's got the cabbage,
corned beef all in
one little crispy thing.
You dip it in
the delicious sauce,
and...like a Reuben in a bite.
GUY: Alright, so what
are we gonna make?
Corned beef for
the Reuben Fritters.
We're gonna make a fritter
out of a Reuben?
-We got to fry it.
-Got to fry it.
Alright, well,
let's get started.
We're gonna add
the pickling seasoning.
So this is a pre-prepared
corned beef?
Exactly. It already
comes in a brine.
This is just to fortify it
with more
of the pickling flavor.
-Exactly.
-Little water into the...
And what temperature
are we going into the oven?
We're gonna go in
at about 400 degrees.
Around about
two to three hours.
We're cooked,
we're cooled.
So now we are going
to dice it up.
♪♪
Look at that.
It's like corned beef
spread.
Ohh. Alright, next up?
Cream cheese, sauerkraut,
Nice.
Swiss cheese --
blocked up.
Now, get personal with it.
I am not even gonna
comment on that.
So now what?
You can't fry it like this
'cause this will
just blow apart.
We're gonna bread it
with a panko bread crumb.
So you form the balls here,
and then we're gonna
go and dredge them?
And how's that
gonna happen?
Flour, buttermilk,
and then panko bread crumbs.
Now, do we let them set up
a little bit
before we fry them?
-Yes.
Okay.
This is the honey
mustard horseradish
dipping sauce
for the Reuben Fritters.
Mayonnaise,
add our local honey,
mustard flour,
granulated garlic,
horseradish.
Copious amounts of that.
And a Guinness mustard.
♪♪
Oh, that's nice.
I like the fact
that you made it yourself.
Good.
Alright, let's get
those fritters.
Time to fry.
Two to three minutes?
Two, three minutes.
Wow, you stack them up
like cannonballs.
-Cannonballs.
-Maybe that was his middle name.
-Reuben Cannonball Fritter?
-Yeah.
[ With Irish accent ] Oh,
Cannonball. He's a great guy.
-[ Normally ] Gonna be hot?
-Probably.
♪♪
Wow. You just have
enough breading
to barely hold
these together,
and it's super
hot and creamy.
Yep.
Just like having
the ultimate Reuben inside,
and it just kind of
melts in your mouth.
-Yep.
-Mmm.
And the mustard sauce
knocks it out of the park.
It's killer, man.
-Nice job.
-Thank you.
-Reuben Fritters.
When you break it open,
the cheese, the corned beef,
everything --
it's just fabulous.
All right,
so what are we gonna make next?
I'll give you a hint --
it's Irish, and it's meatloaf!
We're hangin' out
at Kitty Hoynes
in Syracuse, New York --
when we come back,
the real deal --
see you in a bit.
Welcome back --
we're hanging out
in Syracuse at Kitty Hoynes.
Tell me, my brother.
What is real Irish food?
-Meat and potatoes.
Irish meatloaf.
Irish meatloaf is
crispy on the outside,
it's moist in the middle,
and it's just a great meal.
And it has a leek
cabbage sauce on it --
I like it because
it's homey and delicious.
Okay, fire away.
-Alright, ground beef.
-80/20 or some screwy...
-81/19 this time.
-Yeah, of course it is.
Yes, I know.
Then lamb.
Irish pudding that
was cut up and fried?
Yes.
Nice little flavor
in that.
-White onion.
-A little bit of sweet.
Kind of like a budin.
Basil, oregano, curry.
-Curry in Irish food?
-Curry. Yep.
Granulated garlic,
onion powder,
steak seasoning, eggs.
Now we're gonna add
the panko bread crumbs.
And we put some cheese in.
Irish cheddar -- sharp.
And now we mix it
by hand.
Alright. We're gonna
do our barrier.
Green cabbage leaves.
-So it doesn't stick?
-So it doesn't stick.
Come to Papa.
There we go.
Look at that.
One big loaf?
-One big loaf.
-Wow.
-Alright.
And then on top,
I put celery
so the tinfoil...
-Doesn't stick to it?
-Yes.
Wow.
Well done, Captain.
Thank you.
-And in the oven for how long?
-45 minutes.
-At what temp?
-400.
Bring it out, uncover it,
back in for
another 15 minutes,
and let it get a nice glaze
and nice crunch
on the outside.
Exactly.
And now we're
going to make...?
Cabbage cream sauce.
Garlic.
-Cabbage?
-Cabbage.
You gonna sweat
the cabbage down?
-Sweat it down a bit.
-Okay.
Salt and pepper.
-What is this, soda?
-Sherry.
-Sherry?
-Sherry wine.
[ Singing ] Sweet sherry wine.
-[ Singing ] Ba ba baaaaa.
-[ Normally ] Thank you.
I usually wait
about two minutes,
and then I add the cream.
Okay, so we let that
sit there and simmer down?
Simmer down and
probably reduce...
-Simmer down!
-...about halfway.
And then that
will be ready to serve?
-Be ready to serve.
-Nice.
What's the final step?
-Fold in our basil.
-There we go.
-I like it.
And what do
we serve it with?
The champ potato.
It's an Irish
mashed potato term
for onions in the potatoes.
Talking, like, chives.
Chives. Veggies.
Now we pull it.
Oh! I got you.
I got you.
Where'd you pull that out of,
the center of the earth?
Cut right into it.
Very nice.
Cabbage cream sauce.
♪♪
Love the texture.
Not dry by any means.
Richness of the lamb.
I just got a nice piece
of that sausage
of the pudding sausage,
so it has its nice,
little crunchy texture
because it was fried
ahead of time.
This cabbage cream sauce
with the sherry
and the basil --
just that last little
note of the basil.
Champ potatoes,
fresh veggies.
Dude, real deal.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
-Really good.
SERVER: Irish meatloaf with
cabbage cream sauce.
It's moist and delicious
and feels like home.
That cabbage cream sauce?
I'm illegally
ripping that one off.
You can put that on anything.
WOMAN:
Whatever your appetite,
you're gonna be satisfied
before you leave.
GUY: Awesome place.
This has got all the
characters, all the pieces.
all the craic,
as you would say it.
-And that's what we do.
-You guys rock it.
♪♪
Coming up,
in Des Moines, Iowa...
Ba da ba da bum bum.
...a joint cakin'
some catfish...
That's the real package.
And doin' some 'cuein'.
-Looks good, man.
-All right.
♪♪
You ever notice how,
on "Triple D,"
I visit these
really funky joints
that have, like, crazy names?
Let's see, The Shaved Duck,
Tattooed Moose.
There's Captain Chuck-a-Muck's.
I mean, the list goes on and on,
so here I am in the northwest
region of Des Moines, Iowa,
to check out a joint that's in
the Beaverdale area.
This is the Flying Mango.
Crazy.
It's the best barbecue
in the Midwest.
MAN:
Sliced brisket sandwich.
The smell starts out
in the driveway
because you smell the smoker.
FIERI: Fired up by chef
and owner Mike Wedeking.
Old school, all wood, built it
myself about 20 years ago.
"Built it myself"?
Yep.
And since he opened in 2003,
he's been dishing out cooking
he learned down south
to the folks in the Midwest.
This meat certainly holds up
next to west Texas, Dallas,
Austin.
Got a half-rib dinner,
red beans and rice.
WOMAN: The ribs are served
Memphis style,
and they have awesome rub
on them.
We're gonna make some ribs?
We're gonna make
some rib rub first.
A little paprika, onion powder,
black pepper.
Salt.
Cayenne.
Celery salt,
crushed red pepper flakes.
Whoa!
Garlic powder,
ancho chili powder.
And that comes together
for the rub.
Would you like your ribs, sir?
Baby backs.
Okay, you're gonna flip those,
rub 'em down?
No, I don't do
the back side.
You don't do the back side?
No.
Okay, so out to the smoker,
and what are we smoking with?
Just cherry wood.
How long?
4 1/2, 5 1/2 hours.
Depends on the wind direction.
Next up, barbecue sauce.
Ba da ba da bum bum.
Worcestershire, apple cider,
brown sugar,
little lemon juice,
a little paprika,
cayenne, black pepper,
crushed red pepper,
ancho chili powder,
a little celery salt,
ground yellow mustard,
onion powder, garlic powder.
What is the game called?
"Let's use everything we can
at the Flying Mango"?
Dissolve that a little bit.
Ketchup.
Simmer for
four or five hours.
And we're done.
Looks good, man.
All right.
Half slab of ribs,
our sweet potato pancake,
red beans and rice,
some mango sour cream.
Okay.
The rib is tender.
It pulls off the bone,
doesn't fall off the bone.
Great dry rub.
It's got great bark on it.
Try a little sauce.
Great tang, great acid.
A little bit of sweetness,
enough heat in there.
You get another
whole entrée here
with the red beans
and rice.
The sausage ratio to this
is outstanding.
That's a real package.
Straightforward.
Nice job.
Thank you.
As a former vegetarian,
I can say it's well worth it.
Are you eating that rib
with a fork, sir?
I am.
I'ma kick you out
of this place.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: And when it comes
to digging in here,
well, that's when things
get personal.
WEDEKING: Well, we're known
for our barbecue,
but it's an eclectic mix
of everything I like to eat.
I don't have a fryer,
and I don't do salmon,
and I don't sell hamburgers.
So, you made a menu
about you?
Exactly.
FIERI: Which means
putting that smoker
to use on one of his southern
seafood specialties.
WOMAN: A catfish cake
of collard greens.
Mike does an incredible job
with catfish.
WOMAN #2: Just when you bite
into the catfish cake,
it's a little crunchy
on the outside,
and then you can just taste
the vegetables on the inside.
Now we're into making...
Smoked catfish cakes.
Let's get into it.
Onion, celery, fresh red pepper,
poblano chilies.
You want a nice
smoked catfish.
I like 'em kind of chunky.
Into the bowl.
All right, so we're loaded up
with catfish.
We've got ground coriander,
black pepper, dried basil,
ground cumin, a little salt,
Creole mustard, mayonnaise,
and add a couple
of egg yolks.
Are we gonna bring
the veg in now?
That'd be awesome.
So, there we go.
We put it all together.
Break it down,
still leaving some texture.
Yeah,
I like the nice chunks.
Yeah, all right.
Put this together.
Are we gonna do this
in a pan?
We're gonna build that right
on the flat top.
And what's this gonna get
served with?
Organic collard greens.
Gonna use any pig fat
in there?
Yep.
A little tarragon vinegar,
some onion.
Nice.
Dark brown sugar, fat cap off
the smoked pork shoulder.
And how long
are those gonna cook?
45 minutes.
Dig it.
Here's the cornbread.
Now the greens.
A little of the remoulade.
Wow.
Mmm.
Delicious greens, tender,
and they got a nice bite
to 'em,
a little bit of that tarragon
vinegar coming through.
Those are just humongous chunks
of catfish.
It's delicate.
It's big flavor.
You couldn't make that
any better.
It's absolutely my favorite
thing to eat here.
That's about as real deal
as it comes.
Thank you.
Well played.
The catfish is really juicy
and meaty.
They do an incredible job here
with the collard greens.
They get some of the smoked meat
mixed in.
Catfish cakes.
WOMAN: If somebody's visiting
here the first time,
this is the place that we like
to bring them to.
You just leave
in a good mood, always.
You put a lot of yourself
in this.
I want to put it on a plate
like I'd like to eat it.
Nice job, man.
Really nice.
FIERI: Up next in
Atlantic City, New Jersey...
Let's jump in there.
...I'm making
some new discoveries.
You eat the skin
and everything?
We eat it all.
You suck it down.
From a southern turkey
specialty...
This is the first time
I've ever seen it.
...to my trial run at trotters.
I just wrapped it up
with some pigs' feet.
I'm sorry, some trotters.
Got to love coming down
to Atlantic City.
Always a good time down here,
and I'm about a mile away
from the boardwalk,
also where my restaurant,
The Chophouse, is,
to check out what I hear is a
real-deal southern restaurant.
This is Kelsey & Kim's
Southern Café.
It's just all-around good.
Fried white meat chicken.
Put the soul in soul food.
MAN:
Rib over waffle and chicken!
So, this is my buddy,
Robert.
He's the valet
at the Bally's Hotel,
actually,
where my restaurant is.
This guy's been
doing it forever.
He's saying this place
is legit.
Kelsey's number one.
He bring the south
to south Jersey.
[ Laughs ]
That'd be local chef
Kelsey Jackson
and his wife, Kim,
who started with takeout
only back in '96,
then upgraded to sit
down here in '09.
There's all kind of flavors just
coming out of that kitchen.
Makes your mouth water.
How do you describe soul food
restaurant to people?
Food that you was raised up on
like collard greens,
fried chicken, turkey chops,
pork chops.
What's a turkey chop?
Freeze
a whole turkey breast,
and slice it down on a band saw
and make chops.
Okay, I have been in the food
business all my life.
I mean, that's all I know
is how to cook
and how to do restaurants.
I have never heard
of turkey chop.
[ Laughs ]
Smothered turkey chops.
Have you ever had
a turkey chop?
I have not had a turkey chop.
Did you try
the turkey chop?
She's not sharing.
She doesn't look like
she has such a small,
petite portion, either.
They're definitely
one of my favorites.
We're gonna make the gravy
for the turkey chop.
Start off with a little
clarified butter.
A little flour.
So, we're making the roux.
We're gonna brown our roux.
All right,
we're getting this going.
Onions, gonna whisk that
in real good.
Now we're gonna add
our chicken stock.
So, there's
the gravy for it.
Gonna add
a little black pepper.
And a little kitchen bouquet,
some nice color. Okay.
Next up, time for the turkey
chop, and that is, man.
You're right.
Now we're gonna do
our seasoning.
A little seasoned salt,
granulated garlic,
Cajun seasoning,
and black pepper.
Gotcha.
Mix it nice and good,
add it to the flour.
Gotcha.
And that's it.
No wash or anything,
just putting a little light
coating on 'em.
Light, nice little coating
on 'em.
And they're ready
for the fryer.
Dig it.
How long they cook for?
3 to 5 minutes
in the fryer.
Now we can sauté our onions
and our turkey chops.
Now we add some of
our homemade gravy we made.
Sure love your onions, man.
Yeah, nice onion flavor.
Let that simmer
for a minute.
And they're ready
to be served.
Some rice pilaf,
string beans.
Smothered turkey chops.
Mmm. That's the real deal
right there, brother.
Tastes like
a light pork chop.
Mmm.
Breading's not too heavy,
nice little bit of onion flavor.
You do like your onions.
Yes.
Mmm, nice job.
This is the first time
I've ever seen it.
Nicely done, Kels.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
Smothered turkey chops.
The turkey chops are very good,
very tender.
The smothered gravy brings
everything together.
I love the onions on it.
They're really great.
It's just to perfection.
Kelsey & Kim's is where it's at.
Liver and onions
and a fried onion entrée!
They just give you
so many options.
I loved the candied yams,
black-eyed peas over rice.
FIERI:
And one soul-food specialty
that just dances on your tongue?
MAN: Trotter platter!
The trotters are pig feet.
They're delicious.
You eat trotters?
Absolutely,
grew up on it.
Here we go.
You call 'em trotters,
or you call 'em pigs' feet?
The same thing --
pig feet, trotters.
Gonna have some pigs' feet
on "Triple D," trotters.
How do we do it?
First you start off
with some clean pig feet.
Good idea
on the "clean" part.
Got to clean 'em.
Cut in half, split.
I'm just gonna parboil 'em.
We gonna start 'em up.
How long are they gonna go?
Cook 'em like this for like
45 minutes to an hour.
Drain the water off.
So, that takes all
the impurities out.
There you go.
Got it.
Now we're gonna start off
with some nice ham stock.
Add some celery in here.
Eat the skins
and everything?
You eat it all.
You suck it down.
A little chopped garlic,
a little crushed red pepper.
I like a little spice.
Okay, guess what we're gonna
put in next.
Onion, mm-hmm.
Then we're gonna throw in
some green peppers,
and then finish off
with some vinegar.
And we're gonna let these cook
for, like, another hour,
hour and a half until
the trotters get tender.
Bam, they ready.
Was that a "bam"
you just did?
I'm gonna call Emeril.
[ Laughs ]
The trotters are nice
and tender.
I've had pig tails,
pig ears, headcheese.
I've had snout.
I think I've had
about every part of the pig,
and, ooh, you're just loading it
up, aren't you?
I'm gonna get
some of the stock.
Nothing like
a little foot juice.
There you go.
Wasn't Kevin Bacon in a movie
called "Footjuice"?
Some parsley.
Just jump in there.
That piece right there.
Oh.
They're delicious.
Yes, they are.
Tastes like pork butt.
Kind of got that same texture.
Mm-hmm.
Mm.
It's super tender.
The broth is great with it.
They're dynamite, man.
I've enjoyed all the parts
of the pig now, I think.
I just wrapped it up
with some pigs' feet.
I'm sorry, some trotters.
Some trotters.
Here's your trotters.
Spices,
everything is done just right.
Just the texture, the taste.
You can't mess up here.
Order up,
smothered liver and onions!
A little off the beaten track,
but it's worth finding.
Soul food,
it brings people together.
Everybody's family.
We appreciate all our customers.
I think that's just how you are
as a person,
that everybody is your cousin
coming over for dinner.
That's me.
Good man.
Enjoyed it, man.
So, that's it for
this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Doctor?
[ Laughter ]