Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
It's time to indulge.
You ain't saving
any calories today, Guy.
It's some
rockin' rich recipes.
I'm gonna end up
pushing that car again.
In Los Angeles, California...
Oh!
...A Koreatown
biergarten.
That's impressive!
...Firing up funky,
full-flavored fusion.
Is that
what you were going for?
Yeah, that's
what I was going for.
Gangster.
In Charlotte, North Carolina...
What a great place.
A mother-daughter duo...
Can I lick the bowl?
Sure.
...Serving up the savory
and the sweet.
That is probably
one of the best desserts
I've ever had
on "Triple D."
And on the east side
of Charlotte...
Hey, ho!
...A wild and crazy joint...
You got to come down
for the show.
...Dishing out seafood
with an attitude.
Badda-bing,
right there for you!
Yeah.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm always looking for
great joints
that are serving killer food
served up by real characters.
I mean,
you got Stretch at Grinders,
Reno at Fresh Catch.
Who can forget Donnie D'Alessio
at Queens Comfort.
I mean, the list goes on
and on and on.
So here I am
on the northeast side
of Charlotte, North Carolina.
Badda-bing,
I've found another one!
This is Krazy Fish.
Oh!
Mussels in the window.
It's the best in Charlotte.
Melting pot of good flavor.
Szechuan salmon tacos
for you.
MAN: I think to be
in the restaurant business,
you got to be
a little bit wacky.
Oh!
George
is a little bit wacky.
FIERI: That would be
New York native George Prisco,
who grew up in
his family's restaurant biz
before opening his own brand
of crazy in 2011.
A couple of my friends,
we got together and we decided
to open up a restaurant.
Concept just came along
of welding
a bunch of junk together.
Started welding.
Krazy Fish came about.
The name embodies
kind of the food combinations
they make here.
MAN: Blackened catfish.
It brings a little bit
of the coast to Charlotte.
From the Thai curry snapper
to the mussels.
FIERI: To a loaded up
New Orleans classic.
Gumbo, cornbread
in the window, please!
Fish and pork and shrimp
all put together.
We got our gumbo here.
And were starting off
with a pork butt.
Rub it down, slap it up
with some Jamaican jerk here.
I know a guy
that knows a guy in Jamaica
that sends it to me.
I know a guy...
How long is this
gonna go in the oven?
About four or five hours.
Start it at 350,
and then drop it down
to about 100, 150
for the rest of the way.
Throw it over here.
Over here.
Look at that pork there --
beautiful.
Oh, you know!
Put it in the bowl,
ready to go in.
So we're gonna turn on
our pot over here.
Hit it up with
a little bit of oil.
Gonna add our chicken,
throw some Cajun spice
in there.
Stir that up
a little bit.
And we're getting ready
to throw our shrimps in there.
Shrimps?
Shrimps are shrimps, baby!
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna
add the pork to it
and let this keep
cooking down.
Oil in a hot pot.
Take our onions, peppers --
babarol, we call these.
Babarol!
Throw some celery
in there.
Babarol again.
Little bit of garlic.
Okay, there we go.
Throw that in there.
That guy.
That guy right there.
Welcome to the Rocky Balboa
cooking hour --
live at Krazy Fish.
We getting any okra in here?
We don't put okra in ours.
We put cactus in ours,
huh?
The way we do
our cactus here,
we take it, we boil it,
let it sit overnight.
The next day,
we sauté it.
Gonna add some thyme.
And I'll throw
some curry in there.
My favorite
gumbo ingredient!
Some garam masala.
Yeah, garam masala.
And a bunch
of chicken base.
And then add
a gallon and a half of water.
And then we add
our tomatoes.
Let that come to a boil.
All right, after that,
we're gonna add our roux here.
That's a good-looking roux.
Smells like popcorn.
And it makes you want to eat it
when you smell it.
Gonna take our chicken,
pork, and our shrimp,
toss it in there.
Gonna let this cook down
real good for about 30 minutes.
Cook it up nice.
Mm-hmm.
I'll bowl this up
for you right here.
Badda-bing,
right there for you.
Yeah!
Now you're scaring me.
Mmm!
The flavor's fantastic.
It's not too runny.
The rice tightens things up,
got a good mix
of peppers and onions,
nice garlic pop.
I do enjoy the cactus.
Real deal.
Crazy, but real deal.
This is great gumbo.
The sauce is amazing.
WOMAN:
Lots of bold flavors.
Everything has a little bit
of a kick to it.
Kind of a funky place.
Definitely crazy.
Yeah, there's a mermaid
with a dustpan for a tail.
[ Laughter ]
That's...
Crazy.
MAN: Love the decor,
love the people,
and the food
is excellent every time.
And your seafood diablo.
This right here.
The diablo?
Get it every time.
There's a lot in this --
a lot of shrimp, scallops.
PRISCO: Okay, we're gonna start
our seafood diablo.
Bellissimo.
Yeah!
Butter in there,
get that nice and hot.
We're gonna throw our
cebolla in there, onions.
Our green peppers
and our red peppers.
Get that going.
Then we're gonna add
our scallops in there.
Then we take our...
Shrimps.
Now you got me saying it.
There you go.
Then we take our mahi-mahi,
fresh cut.
And we're gonna start
adding our spices.
We add our sriracha.
We add our Valentina sauce.
Oh, you're taking a little
Mexican to it, okay.
Oh, yeah.
We got the chipotle next.
Chipotle adobo!
Salt and pep.
And lots of that.
Our Cajun spice.
We're gonna add our garlic.
Nice.
Beautiful.
Gonna add our turmeric.
A little bit of sug.
Half and half,
some heavy cream.
Oh, hang on.
I'll get you the kitchen sink.
That's the only thing
not in there.
Plate it up.
Couple nice
flour tortillas here.
Throw some scallions on top,
some cilanch.
Cilanch!
There we go.
The dish is gonna knock you
to the ground.
Knock me to the ground.
Yes.
It's got a nice little bit
of heat.
It's definitely rich.
Tons of flavor.
I mean, no question.
I understand
why it's called Krazy Fish.
Booya!
Perfect example.
The spice in it is perfect,
good blend of curry flavors.
You know, it all comes together
in a great dish.
I like everything
about this place.
Pulled pork tacos up!
Now you know
where the name came from.
Yeah.
One word -- crazy.
With a "K."
A fun place to come.
You put a ton of enthusiasm,
a ton of energy,
a ton of respect --
the way you run it,
the way you decorate it.
Got to come down
for the show.
Ah, very crazy.
Oh! Hey, ho!
FIERI:
Coming up, a Korean-German combo
in Los Angeles....
Spot-on, brother.
....Where beer
makes the bird...
Holy cooked up
glazed bird!
And there's a lot more than beef
in their burgers.
I could eat one of those
every day.
So I'm here on the edge
of Koreatown in Los Angeles,
right down the street
from Beer Belly,
remember that place?
The duck? Oh!
Anyhow, I'm here to check out
this Korean restaurant
where they've got
the traditional environment
and the traditional menu --
[ Needle scratches on record ]
Not so much.
No, this is Biergarten --
fusion grill and craft beer.
German fried rice!
I've never seen Korean-German
combination before.
It's food that, literally,
you can't get anywhere else.
Korean fried chicken
with French toast.
Koreatown obviously has a lot
of different fusion places.
Not German and Korean.
FIERI: But that didn't stop
owner Neil Kwon
from playing matchmaker.
kimchi short rib
fried rice.
What gave you
the inspiration to do
a Korean fusion
funky craft beer joint?
After college,
we backpacked through Europe.
One of the stops, Germany.
If anything,
I wanted to capture that vibe.
With the help
of Chef Eddie Hah,
who started mixing things up
in the kitchen in 2011.
HAH: One tempura fries.
MAN:
He's extremely passionate
about everything
he's serving here.
Drunken chicken C3.
It's called drunken chicken
because they brine it in beer.
MAN: It's very moist.
Got a great crust on it.
Just perfect.
What are we making?
The beer brine
for the drunken chicken.
Is that
a typical Korean dish?
No, it's not.
I dig it.
Let's get after it.
All right.
I'm gonna go ahead
and put the Korean beer.
Hai!
Hai! Right.
Water. We're gonna go ahead
and put that honey in there.
Some parsley.
Half lemons.
A lot of them.
And garlic -- peeled.
Add some bay leaf.
Bay leaf, a Korean food?
No.
Just checking.
Dry oregano,
some kosher salt,
and some black pepper.
Fire it up and then...
then we'll brine.
Yeah.
Give that
a little stir.
Harry Potter called,
he wants his spoon.
Basically, we just
want the salt to dissolve.
Salt dissolves,
bring the flavors together,
and that's our brine
that we're gonna use
for our chicken.
Yes.
Okay.
So we have our brine here now,
it's at room temp.
It smells a little like
a sweet tea.
You want to smell that?
No, I'll smell it,
and then you'll probably
push my head in there.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna go ahead
and add the chicken.
Down into the party bowl.
And how long are we gonna
hold the chicken?
About 24 hours.
So now
that these have brined,
we're gonna add the beer
to the stems.
And what kind of beer
is this?
This is
a Guinness, actually.
a dark stout, okay.
And then I'm just gonna go ahead
and pat this dry,
I'll go ahead and season with
salt, pepper, and some oil.
Push the chicken down,
right into the cavity,
and into the oven
at about 400 degrees
for about 35 minutes.
Got it.
Holy cooked up
glazed bird!
That's impressive!
I'm gonna cut
right down the center,
and we'll go ahead
and plate that
with our
cabbage frisee salad
and garnish it with a pickled
jalapeno and pickled diakon.
All right, and that's it?
That's it.
Oh!
We like to do
beer can chicken,
but I don't think I've ever
had one that's infused
and has this much flavor
of beer.
You get some of that nice
roasted flavor from the skin,
then you get
a little bite of that slaw...
A little bite
of that jalapeno.
Mmm!
Chef, nicely done.
Thank you, Chef.
MAN: The skin's crispy,
the meat's juicy.
I get it
every time I come here.
These are three of my buddies
from "Guy's Grocery Games,"
Eric, Gabe, and Francesco.
What do you think
of the chicken?
It's so flavorful.
Like, I didn't think it
would be this flavorful.
The beer, the honey --
it's perfect.
It's silly
how juicy it is.
how juicy it is?
Yeah.
How do you describe
the menu to people?
Oh, man, just anything
and everything
that pairs well with beer.
FIERI: That would be
25 types of craft beer,
tapped alongside everything
from kimchi pancakes
to German sausage...
One wurstplatte, C5.
...And a unique take
on the burger.
The meat
is completely unique
to any other burger
in Los Angeles.
All right,
what are we making next?
The Chosun burger.
"Chosun" actually means
"Korea" in Korean.
Why didn't you just
say "Korea"?
I wanted it to sound like
it's the chosen burger.
Is that
what you were going for?
Yeah, that's
what I was going for.
Gangster.
I'm making some kimchi.
All right.
We're gonna halve
the napa cabbage.
Salt?
Four cups of salt.
So this is like
quick kimchi?
It's somewhat quick.
The cabbage will now sit
at room temp for 24 hours.
We're gonna bring it back,
rinse it,
and then hit it
with the paste.
Yeah. kimchi paste.
We'll start with
a little bit of water
and then onion.
Red pepper flakes,
fish sauce, sugar,
garlic -- whole garlic.
Lots of it.
Lots of it. And ginger.
Baby shrimp.
Pulse this.
Add the Korean pear.
Pear?
You want to try that?
That's good.
Delicious.
More like apple.
Add the Korean radish next.
So blend this up.
Now we take that,
and we're gonna brush
it onto each leaf.
Each leaf.
We're gonna let it sit out
for 24 hours,
and then throw it
into the wok.
So it gets funky,
and then it's chili funky.
Chili funky.
Okay.
All right, now we're into
the Chosun One burger.
We have a patty that we do 50/50
with beef and pork,
and we add
a little bit of tofu,
which is a Korean thing,
actually.
So now it's 110%
110%.
So that's it?
And salt, pepper on the outside.
Onto the grill.
Fantastic.
We're gonna add some
grilled Spam, Korean bacon.
Korean bacon!
All right,
we're gonna start off
with a little bit of mustard
on the bottom bun.
Then we're gonna add
some of our sautéed kimchi.
So you are allowed to cook
kimchi after you've done it.
It gets better
when you sauté it.
Really?!
Yeah. Man, it does.
Okay.
The hamburger patty.
A little bit of
the pickled diakon.
Red pepper aioli.
We're gonna go ahead
and add the Spam.
And some fries.
What's the coating
on the fry?
It's a little
tempura batter.
Mmm!
If someone were to say,
"I'm gonna make you a hamburger,
but I'm gonna Korean-ize it,"
that's what that is.
Great texture, a lot of meat,
acid, sweet, crunch,
all there.
Mmm! Awesome burger.
Thank you.
I could eat one of those
every day.
MAN:
The patty is unique.
It just really falls apart
when you take a bite.
It's one of the best burgers
in L.A., easily.
This is my buddy Skrape
from TapouT,
Julian Edelman,
number 11 from the Patriots.
You got a funky biergarten
in Koreatown.
Break it down.
Tell me
what's in this first.
It's good. I don't know
what's in it, but it's good.
So Julian and I do
a great program
called "Best Buddies"
in Boston with Tom Brady,
helping intellectually
disabled adults.
In your regiment of training
for the season,
this is the kind of food
you're allowed to eat?
Yeah. You know, a complex carb
with the rice,
High in protein.
I'd say it's pretty much
a great meal.
You will leave full, happy,
and comfortable.
FIERI:
You want a funky joint,
great beer, eclectic menu --
come see this guy.
Thank you, Chef.
Spot-on, brother.
FIERI: Up next, in Charlotte,
North Carolina...
Boy, the flavor's
nice in there.
...A real deal
home-style hangout...
I've got a spotter now
when I eat.
...Right down
to the dessert.
I want, like,
16 of them to go.
So a lot of people don't know,
but my mom, Penny, was raised
here in North Carolina.
I love coming back.
I mean,
there's so much history.
So I'm in Charlotte.
And you know what?
To find a restaurant
in a building
that was built in the year 1900,
that's pretty incredible.
What's more incredible
is that you got
a mother and daughter team
that are serving up
an eclectic scratch-made menu.
This is 300 East.
French onion soup
is in the window.
300 East is about the most
welcoming place in town.
The sweet potato
ravioli.
My favorite thing
changes every week.
Entrée crab cake up.
Everything you eat
is unique.
It's like
a classic American menu
with some
kind of surprise.
FIERI: Which is no surprise
to the locals,
'cause owner Cathy Coulter
opened doors in this house
way back in 1986.
The building
is from the year 1900.
Is that a big deal
to folks?
It is because so many
of Charlotte's old buildings
have been torn down.
FIERI:
But Cathy prefers to build.
So in 2000, she brought
in daughter Ashley
as general manager
and pastry chef.
Chocolate bread pudding.
FIERI: And in 2001,
Chef Kristine Schmidt
came on to spearhead
the savory side of things.
Lamb and mushroom ragout
in the window.
It's a hearty dish.
You'll fill up on it.
And what do we start with,
leg of lamb?
SCHMIDT: Yeah,
boneless leg of lamb here.
You want to pour a little bit
of olive oil in that pan?
I got you.
All right,
so we drop this in.
We sear this
on both sides.
I'm gonna season this.
Salt and pepper.
We're ready
for the braising.
A little bit of onion in,
carrots, celery.
Some whole garlic cloves.
I'm down with it.
Some fresh thyme sprigs.
S. and P.?
Got to get
that flavor in there.
Nice bottle of wine.
[ Imitates
pouring liquid ]
[ Laughs ]
All right.
And then
just enough cold water.
Just to float
a little bit.
Put a piece of parchment paper
on there
and then cover it with foil.
What temp is this
gonna cook off at?
375.
For about four hours?
Oh, four, four and a half.
Shred it.
We also strain out
the braising liquid.
Next step?
All right.
So we're
gonna start the sauce.
We reserve that lamb fat.
I love it.
A little bit
of fresh rosemary.
Bloom that rosemary,
then hit the new cloth.
Oh, yeah.
Onion,
celery, carrots.
Sweat it down.
Where were you
on Saturday night?!
[ Chuckles ]
Pun.
Different kind
of sweating it.
Add in some more wine
to glaze.
Then I'm gonna go in with..
Some garlic.
Crushed red pepper.
I like this.
And cinnamon.
That is the kicker!
Crushed tomatoes.
And then the braising liquid
that we saved.
Oh, that's nice.
Tomato paste.
Now we're just gonna add
a little salt and pepper.
Then we'll drop
the mushrooms in.
Word.
And then
we go to our lamb.
And get all that lamb
in here.
Look at that!
Oh, man!
Had Def Leppard
just tried that,
they would have called the song
"Pour Some Lamb Ragout On Me."
The video would have been
different.
All right.
Got our
goat cheese ravioli down.
Did someone
locally mix those?
Yes, they do.
We provide the filling for them,
and they stuff it for us.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Let's just get
some of that
right in on the center
of them raviolis.
Okay.
Want to put a little bit
of what we call goat butter.
Nice fresh sprig of mint.
Done.
Mmm!
Boy, the flavor's nice
in there.
Oh, yeah. You definitely
pick up the mushroom.
I keep getting more and more
depth of flavor every bite.
Outstanding.
Oh, good.
Glad you like it.
Mmm.
I'm a professional.
I've got a spotter now
when I eat.
Mm-hmm.
Lamb and mushroom ragout.
The sauce, it just ties
each piece together.
This is, like,
the best thing I ever ate.
Veggie black bean tortilla.
Of course, the food's immense,
but the vibe here is great.
It welcomes you in,
it feels good and homey.
FIERI:
Walk across the tile floor,
you see the old
fireplace mantle here.
I mean, it really has
that warm feeling about it.
And there's food you like.
FIERI: Especially if you're
in the mood for dessert.
The ice cream sandwich is well
worth a visit to 300 East.
I'm going from this
to an ice cream sandwich?
Yep, yep, yep.
You ain't saving
any calories today, Guy.
I'm gonna end up pushing
that car again.
[ Laughs ]
Coming back to North Carolina
in a little bit. See ya.
Welcome back. Hanging out
in Charlotte, North Carolina,
at 300 East with --
don't smile.
[ Laughs ]
There we go.
I wanted to make sure.
I was told I wasn't able
to make her laugh.
FIERI: That's 'cause
pastry chef Ashley Boyd
takes her desserts seriously --
right down
to old-fashioned desserts.
WOMAN: Butterscotch
ice cream sandwich.
Other than my mom's house,
I probably
won't get any other
homemade
ice cream sandwiches.
Okay,
so what are we making?
First, we're gonna make
the molasses cookies.
So we couldn't just
buy the cookie.
No.
We're gonna
make the cookie.
Of course.
So let's get into this.
All right.
Unsalted butter,
granulated sugar.
And then we're gonna let it go
for about three minutes.
So we cream the sugar.
This is a gluten-free flour mix
that I make here.
Get it going.
We have baking soda,
kosher salt,
ground cinnamon.
Ginger?
Ground ginger.
Chia seed.
Ch-ch-ch-chia!
Mm-hmm.
And some fresh nutmeg.
Mix that together.
Incorporate it evenly.
Next step.
Add the molasses.
Next, we add the eggs?
One at a time.
Now we add in the dry mix.
So we'll take this now?
Now we scoop it
into dough balls,
put it in some sugar.
We're just gonna
roll them around.
Mm-hmm.
You're very precise.
Very gentle, very...
[ Soft music plays ]
That's very elegant.
Yes.
Well, it's those sausage fingers
that say elegance.
So these are gonna go
for 18 minutes at what temp?
350.
When are we gonna
make the ice cream?
Let's do it.
We're gonna melt
some unsalted butter
and some brown sugar.
Heavy cream
and whole milk.
That's coming to a simmer.
What's next?
So then we take some egg yolks,
brown sugar, and salt.
And we're gonna
temper this in?
We are.
So you pour in about
1/3 of the hot cream.
So then this can
just go back in.
It needs to get up to
175, 180.
I will strain it,
put it in an ice-bath,
and then we add the vanilla.
Let this cool down.
It doesn't have to
be ice-cold, right?
It needs to be ice-cold.
It's got to be ice-cold,
just what I was saying.
And then we'll go
to the machine.
So the ice cream
is churned.
Scoop it all out.
And it needs to firm up.
Can I lick the bowl?
Sure. Go for it.
[ Laughs ]
So now this goes in the freezer
for four hours.
All right. Cookies are ready,
ice cream's ready.
Hit it.
And some of our
caramelized pineapple,
nasturtium petal.
That's pretty.
Thank you.
Mmm. That is probably
one of the best desserts
I've ever had
on "Triple D."
Oh, thanks.
This is the definition
of how ice cream sandwiches
started.
Make the cookie yourself,
outstanding.
Ice cream is delicious.
The whole presentation --
dynamite.
Thank you.
I want, like,
16 of them to go.
Awesome. Done.
Ice cream sandwich
in the window.
It's creamy and scrumptious.
Just close to heaven.
And the ahi tuna salad.
It's a really cool melting pot
in every way.
What a great place.
Eclectic, creative,
and the food's great.
Thank you.
Good job.
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Where are we gonna
make these cookies,
down in the basement?
Oh, let's go.
Okay.
[ Laughter ]