Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
on a special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
in Tuscany.
And we're eating up
all the regional favorites...
Real-deal, authentic,
rustic Italian food.
...like legit
handmade pasta...
So simple,
but prepared so perfectly.
...fresh Mediterranean
seafood...
Look at how beautiful
this is.
...lights-out local lamb...
Tell me
that doesn't look amazing.
...and Tuscan
with an off-the-hook twist.
Shut the back door.
Plus, I finally get my hands
on truffles
that couldn't be any fresher.
Pulling it
right out of the ground.
Oh, man.
From scenic hilltops...
This is worth the plane ticket
to Italy by itself.
...to picture-perfect
villages...
Unforgettable.
...it's buon appetito
all the way.
W.O.W.!                  W.O.W.!
So, I'm here
in the town of Collodi,
partway between
Florence and Pisa.
This is the birthplace
of Pinocchio,
but it's also the birthplace
of the idea of having
a "Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
tour through Italy.
Oh, the food here's fantastic.
The owner --
He is one of a kind.
And the experience --
unforgettable.
This is Mangiafuoco.
[ Speaks Italian ]
The food is very good.
It's more authentic.
I think it's authentic.
FIERI: That's what hooked me
two years ago
when I was traveling
through Italy.
Matt Nagan and I
shot the Schellville Grill
in Sonoma, California.
He introduces me
to these two.
They say one night,
"Let's go to dinner.
We're gonna take you to this
place called Mangiafuoco."
And out comes out the man.
That would be crazy man
Massimo Iacopini,
who opened this joint
with his wife, Sonia Pascucci,
in '05.
Massimo is a character.
[ Speaks Italian ]
I like people.
I like my life.
The food in Mangiafuoco --
How do you describe it?
Natural food.
Country food.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Everything is fresh,
and this is important.
Spaghetti Mangiafuoco.
The spaghetti with the capers
and fresh cherry tomatoes.
It's fantastic.
I love it.
You can taste everything
of Italy in one dish.
The Spaghetti Mangiafuoco.
Okay.
Let's go.
Olio d'oliva.
Okay,
extra virgin olive oil.
Aglio.
Okay, the garlic.
Cappero.
Capers.
Acciuga.
Anchovy.
Your recipe?
Chef is Sonia.
I test.
This is the test kitchen?
[ Both laughing ]
Beautiful tomatoes.
I mean,
that's one of the things.
Getting tomatoes in Italy is
just a totally different thing.
[ Speaks Italian ]
Peperoncino.
Spaghetti.
We'll finish the pasta
in the sauce?
Look a that.
It's very al dente.
It's light.
It's got a little bit
of spice to it.
The tomatoes bring it out.
I really think the kicker
for the whole thing
is the little bit
of anchovy.
Mmm.
Very simple, but...
Very wonderful.
Like you.
[ Laughter ]
The pasta's really good.
It was really spicy.
Give you the spark.
MAN: That's phenomenal.
Not too many ingredients,
but all fresh.
FIERI: And local, like the story
that comes from this place.
Is where the Pinocchio story
came from.
Written by Carlo Lorenzini.
You can see characters of
his novel all around his place.
Which adds
to the whole Italian experience.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
I like the lamb.
Cooked with potatoes, pepper,
and Tuscan olives.
Other people make lamb,
but nobody makes it like this.
FIERI: All right,
I know we got lamb.
Lamb alla ciociara.
Alla shosha.
Cho. Cho. Ciociara.
Choo-choo!
Choo-choo-ciara.
Ciociara.
Bravo.
Okay. Andiamo.
Olio.
Cipolla.
Pomodori.
Cappero.
Oliva.
Peperone Latina.
Now, we call this
a red bell pepper.
[ Speaks Italian ]
So the potatoes
from Tuscany.
Sale.
Pepe.
Pepe. Si.
Don't kill me, please!
Aah!
Where's the lamb from?
Ciociaria.
Bravo.
Okay.
[ Speaks Italian ]
[ Whistles ]
Little pepe.
Pepe.
Okay.
Tell me
that doesn't look amazing.
Vino bianco.
Okay.
We're gonna add
some of the white wine.
Okay, now to the oven.
[ Stammering ]
Hey. Perfect.
Venti minuti.
Hey!
Oh, fantastic.
Buon appetito.
[ Laughs ]
Mm.
Simple, complete,
outrageous.
The lamb's got a great, deep,
rich flavor.
But as tender
as can be.
Real-deal, authentic,
rustic Italian food
in the village
of Pinocchio.
Grazie.
The lamb is fantastic.
WOMAN: It's simple.
It's not real complicated,
and it's not real fancy.
Just flavorful.
NAGAN: You come here, and it's
like you don't want to leave,
It's, like, you're here
for the night.
You want to stay.
Listen, my friend,
without question, in my life,
this is one of my favorite
restaurants.
Grazie.
The experience that you have
here is unforgettable.
Hey, you want to dance
with me?
Let's go.
[ Both laugh ]
I'm out.
FIERI: Up next, we're hopping
over to Montecatini Alto...
♪ Howl, howl, howl ♪
...for some serious seafood...
That is out of bounds.
...served
on top of the world.
Worth the drive.
Go up the hill.
Whew!
Awesome weather.
So, I'm in an area
known as Montecatini,
about 15 kilometers
away from Collodi.
Down there, that's Terme.
They got these great spas.
Up here, this is Alto.
We're on top of the mountain.
And I'm here
to check out a joint
that's known for its...
fresh seafood?
I guess that's why they call
this place W.O.W.
[ Speaks Italian ]
If you want to eat good fish,
we come here.
Lobster with crabs.
It's classic Italian food...
Pick up gnocchi, please.
...with a little bit
of elevation.
FIERI: That's because hometown
chef Alessandro Giuntoli
is mixing
the Italian cooking skills
he learned from his nonna...
Pick up the lobster Catalana,
please.
...with a passion
for Mediterranean seafood.
Black linguine, squid.
The taste
is really, really good.
It's fantastic.
We're gonna make
a squid-ink linguine.
What are we gonna do first?
Gonna deep fry the peppers?
Deep fry the peppers.
Just gonna drop them
right in there.
Yes.
While that's working,
what do we do next?
We peel the shrimp.
This is raw.
Look at this pink,
little shrimp.
Okay,
now we're gonna do the...
Calamari.
So take the skins off?
Yes.
Some strips. Okay.
Slice.
Are these ready?
Yes.
It's like bobbing
for peppers.
I got it!
[ Laughs ]
Next up?
Slice the lardo.
Yeah, I use that
when I go in the sun.
I put some on.
It's cured,
but not smoked.
It's just the fat.
It's the belly.
So, we're gonna cook this down
until crispy?
Yeah.
Okay, now...?
Garlic.
Shaved garlic, so it's not
gonna burn very fast.
A little peperoncino.
Yeah.
Okay.
Tons of peppers.
We got to get those peppers
in fast,
because otherwise,
we're gonna burn the garlic.
Next?
Squid-ink linguine.
The squid ink is really
the ink in the squid...
Yes, from the squid.
...that is used to color
the pasta,
but that doesn't change
the flavor.
If I were ZZ Top...
♪ Howl, howl, howl ♪
[ Laughs ]
Now I add the shrimp.
Okay.
Add the calamari, linguine.
Look at that.
You're gonna finish the last
part of the cooking right there
and let the pasta absorb it.
Okay, and now we can plate.
Okay.
Beautiful.
And then we finish
with the dry-aged ricotta.
Dry-aged ricotta.
Whatever happened
to the little bacon?
We're gonna put it
on the top.
Look at that.
And we're done.
Gorgeous.
This dish is so simple,
but prepared so perfectly.
That is out of bounds.
The calamari is fresh,
and it's super tender.
The shrimp, also fresh,
and you saw
how beautiful that was.
Just nice and pink.
And then we've got this
handmade pasta cooked al dente.
This is worth the plane ticket
to Italy by itself.
Nice job.
WOMAN:
Linguine, squid ink.
The food is fantastic.
FIERI: And the view
ain't too shabby, either...
On a very clear day, you can see
the villages down below.
FIERI: ...which is
just a funicular ride away.
I love the atmosphere
and of course the food.
FIERI:
Like this seafood sensation...
King prawn.
...served on top
of a deep-fried artichoke.
The prawns are beautiful
and really, really good.
All right,
so let's get into this.
We're gonna clean
the artichoke.
We take the leaf.
We're gonna
just get rid of those.
We're gonna cut
from the bottom to the top.
Take off the skin.
'Cause you can eat
that stem.
Yeah.
And then we open
the leaves.
So, now we take these.
We drop them in the fryer
for how long?
10, 15 minutes.
10 or 15 minutes?
Yes.
Minutos?
Minuto.
Olive oil.
King prawn.
King prawns.
One by one.
And we leave the head on
for the flavor, right?
Yes. Sea salt.
And then honey chestnut.
The what?
Chestnut honey.
Honi?
Oh, honey!
[ Both laugh ]
And then brandy.
Oh, of course you should.
It's beautiful.
Okay.
Then finish
with just a cube of butter.
Now we grab the artichokes.
This dish has already started
to take another level,
just in the time
and the energy
that Chef is taking
to put it together.
Look at how beautiful
this is.
Warming up the sauce.
And just finish.
Tender, little sweet,
little kiss of the brandy.
The sauce is nice and light.
And the artichoke --
It's simple,
it's what's in season.
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
The man, right here.
Pick up the king prawn,
please.
It's very fresh
and high-quality.
The flavors all mix together.
Very tasty.
Worth the drive.
Go up the hill.
Find the joint.
W.O.W.
"Wow" is right.
W.O.W.!                  W.O.W.!
[ Both laugh ]
FIERI: Coming up...
we're headed south
to San Miniato...
This is crazy.
...for a bucket-list
adventure...
The whole experience
is based off a 2-year-old dog?
...that's all about
the truffles.
Aha! I got it.
So, here I am, taking
a little break from "Triple D,"
because I am in the land
of truffles.
I'm about 50 miles west
of Florence.
So, here's the deal.
Truffles form below the soil,
near the tree roots.
They're super expensive.
They're like buried treasures.
They're decadent, flavorful,
and really rare.
Plus, they're one of my favorite
things in the world
to cook with.
So when I heard we could
actually go truffle hunting
here in Italy,
forget about it, I'm going.
I grabbed a couple
of my American buddies,
and we're hooking up
with the experts.
This is my buddy Fabio.
Fabio, what's up, brother?
Nice to see you.
And this is the truffle man.
Riccardo.
The truffle guy.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Are we gonna hunt with a pig,
a dog? What do we got?
FABIO:
Turbo. We have Turbo.
[ Speaks Italian ]
This is our truffle dog?
Yes.
How old is Turbo?
2 years old.
2 years old?
The whole experience
is based off a 2-year-old dog?
Yes.
Turbo never fails.
Turbo never fails?
Never.
This I want to see.
We just follow the dog?
We just follow Turbo,
which is a special breed
for hunting the truffle.
And why are we using
a dog and not a pig?
I always heard
about the pig.
Because the pig
eats the truffle.
You can't pull
the pig off?
You can't pull the pig off
from the truffle.
All right.
Let's go.
[ Speaks Italian ]
FIERI: When Turbo stops
and starts to get his dig on,
everybody just...
And, then,
he doesn't find any.
All right,
come on, Turbo.
Why this region
are there more truffles?
The soil,
the climate is perfect.
Perfect.
There's no rhyme or reason
why the truffle's there
or not there.
I mean, that's why they can't
cultivate truffles.
That's why they's so expensive.
That's probably why
they're cherished so much,
besides the fact
that they taste awesome.
But this is crazy.
Just wondering
around the field,
looking for a tuber
that grows on the root
that's gonna be dug up
by a dog.
[ Whistles ]
Turbo.
[ Speaks Italian ]
He's on it?
Uh-huh.
Turbo. Turbo!
[ Laughs ]
[ Speaks Italian ]
Oh, Turbo's going nuts.
This is how I get
about truffles.
I just can't dig that hard.
Oh, man.
So that's it right there?
The dirt smells
like truffle.
[ Speaks Italian, whistles ]
Okay.
So, okay, just...
Whoa!
That...
Pulling it
right out of the ground.
Oh, man.
Good job.
Turbo.
Good job, Turbo.
Once he got after it,
we had to get after it.
Thank goodness
we got Turbo.
Uh-huh. I got it.
Listen, that was
bucket-list stuff right there.
But I got one more joint
I got to check out
before I leave Italy.
It's north of here,
in the city of Lucca...
My mouth is just firing up
for this.
...where they're serving up
traditional Tuscan dishes...
Oh, that is delicious.
...along with a little
improvisation.
The Italian judges
give him a 9!
So, here we are on a rainy day,
wrapping up
this Tuscany "Triple D" tour.
Now, I am in the city of Lucca,
inside the walls of Lucca.
I mean, there is so much to do,
so much to see,
even on a rainy day.
But the one question that still
remains is, where do I eat?
From what I'm told,
this is a joint you can't miss.
This is Port Ellen Clan.
Here we get the mackerel.
It's Italian, light food.
Traditional,
but at the same time elegant.
Codfish for gentleman.
I love to come to a restaurant
that shows the passion
and then the character
of the owner.
FIERI: That would be
Chef Leonardo Calo,
who's been serving Tuscan food
with a twist here...
Mussel carbonara.
FIERI: ...since 2012.
Where are you from?
I was born in Pisa.
There's something else
going on in the accent
you're not telling me.
I tried to cook, first of all,
in England.
Leonardo is not afraid
to be influenced
by international food.
The oxtail tortelli.
It's a very peculiar
interpretation of tortelli.
What are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
one of our favorite dishes,
the oxtail tortellis.
First of all,
the fresh-pressing olive oil,
which is made
three days ago.
Let me try this.
Shut the back door.
We have carrots,
celery, and onion.
Sage and rosemary.
I love both of them.
Crush the garlic like that.
And now we're gonna work
on the oxtail.
Some olive oil.
The Italian judges
give him a 9!
Welsh salt.
Welsh.
Yes, you should put some on.
Black pepper.
Now we add the oxtail
to the vegetables.
The red wine from Tuscany.
Cover the oxtail with water.
Just a little bit.
And now we are working
a very low temperature
for three hours.
So let it cool.
Shred it off the bone.
We have to go now
with the bread.
We get the oxtails.
Okay.
So, we're gonna let the bread
soak up all the jus.
We're gonna make
a party happen.
Yeah, okay.
Parmesan cheese.
And now we're gonna add
the eggs.
And then,
we'll get some pasta sheets,
and we start to do it.
That is an egg wash.
There you go.
So, I like that you make
the pasta by hand.
Now I cut it and form it
into tortelli.
Next, they are gonna go
in the water now.
Okay.
Now is the reduction
of the oxtail and the carrots
together with a touch of butter
and sherry vinegar.
Okay.
Now we get the tortelli.
Just let it coat that
a little bit.
Okay. That's it.
So, now we add
the Vezzena cheese,
the olive oil.
Very nice.
Wow.
That olive oil is in a different
class all by itself.
Do you mind if I try some?
Oh, please, please, please.
You know, my favorite part
about the whole thing
is that little kiss
of that vinegar.
The pasta has bite.
Incredibly flavorful.
The texture
is nice and creamy.
I mean,
all of it is delicious.
One of the best tortelli
in Lucca.
They are perfect with red wine.
When you come to a city
like this, you don't know
what is local,
what is tourist,
and this is kind of
off the beaten path.
And when you come
into your restaurant,
it's like coming
into somebody's home.
I think that is what
I was looking for.
The quality of the ingredients
is really very good,
using the tradition of Lucca
and some creative approach.
What are we gonna make next?
The carbonara mussel.
Instead of the bacon,
which is a traditional recipe,
we use the mussel.
Should we drop the pasta?
This is like
short, fat rigatoni.
Yeah.
All right,
so now we take
all the mussels
that are cooked
out of the shell,
saving the liquid.
Okay, so, we work
with the mussel
and the water
of the mussel.
We remove the pasta
from the boiling.
We have generous
Parmesan cheese on the top.
That's gonna make a nice, little
sauce with the mussel water.
And then we add
only the yoke of the eggs.
Gonna work it in.
Great.
Beautiful dish.
Now we're gonna add
the Parmesan cheese.
We add the pepper now
with a touch of olive oil.
My mouth is just firing up
for this.
Very impressive.
You like your pasta al dente,
my friend,
and that is how
I like mine.
What I love,
you've allowed mussels
to take the place of pancetta.
It's refined.
It definitely has its
respectable notes and accents
and representations.
I'm impressed, man.
Thank you very much
for having me.
Really, I got to tell you, man,
you're a good cat.
[ Speaks Italian ]
The mix of the eggs, cheese,
and mussels --
They test very well.
I watch you and I listen
and things are very precise,
but then you have
a wild side.
That is one of the best things
they say to me
in the last 20 years.
So, you're blond,
but you're not a nice girl,
because if you was a nice girl,
I would kiss you, okay?
You're a good friend.
I really like
friends like you.
Was that a great "Triple D" tour
in Italy or what?
I got to tell you,
there's just one last thing.
You know,
you haven't been able to drive
on top of the walls of Lucca
since '85,
but when you got
a nice, red Ferrari like this,
well, you just have to --
You know what I mean?
I'll see you next time on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."