I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Aah!
...we're taking
an international tour...
This is where things are gonna
get interesting.
...smack dab in the middle
of California.
I can't eat any more.
First, in Bakersfield...
Holy moly.
...the authentic Greek spot...
Oh, those are so good.
...serving up a hearty helping
of home.
Made with a lot of love
and a lot of care.
Then, across town...
Forget about it.
...old-country European
specialties...
Now you're showing off.
...making for
a multi-course meal.
If I lived in this town,
this would be a place
that I would visit
at least once a week.
And nearby, in Taft...
Dig that.
...the totally legit
Asian joint...
I've had it good.
This was great.
...dishing out an unforgettable
experience.
I can't even tell you
how good this is.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm here on the northwest side
of Bakersfield, California,
in an area known as Rosedale,
and I'm in a strip mall,
of course.
And they got
all your basics here.
They got the nutrition store,
paint store, a few salons,
and of course, they've got
a Greek restaurant.
[ Record scratches ]
Wait a second.
A Greek restaurant in
Bakersfield, California?
You know it.
This is Athena's Greek Cafe
and Bakery.
The food's fantastic.
Service.
Meatballs.
This is the only authentic Greek
restaurant in town,
and it's really good.
FIERI: A bit surprising
since one of the owners
isn't even Greek.
What nationality are you?
Mexican American.
I grew up loving the Greek
culture as a child.
I said I was gonna
have a daughter,
and I was gonna
name her Athena,
but I didn't know I was
gonna marry a Greek man.
Opa!
FIERI: And she didn't know
she was gonna open
a Greek restaurant
named after her daughter,
either,
but that's exactly what
Letty and Elias Skapinakis
did in 2012.
MAN:
It's sort of out of the way.
It's sort of a hidden gem.
And the food is always
incredible here.
Dolmades.
Dolmades are a stuffed
cabbage leaf
with a lemon sauce.
I'm from Greece, and it is
like we used to have them
back home.
We're gonna make
cabbage dolmades.
Dolmades.
Right.
We're gonna start out
with our ground beef,
pureed onions.
Those will just cook down
and disappear.
But the flavor
will be there.
Eggs.
Fresh mint.
Dill.
Some black pepper.
There you go.
Some salt, some rice.
Greek olive oil.
So, mix this all together.
Gently.
Meat-rice mixture
is ready to go.
Cabbage has been steamed.
Let's go.
Cabbage dolmades is something
you're gonna find
in a Greek home.
What you find
at a Greek restaurant
is going to be
the stuffed grape leaves,
and this is more of
a comfort way of doing them.
She has a little
Barefoot Contessa style.
Very soothing way
of speaking.
All right.
We'll move along here.
[ Both laugh ]
Put a little bit of water
in there.
Do a swirl of olive oil,
some salt,
and they're gonna simmer
for 45 minutes.
Now, lemon sauce.
We're gonna start out
with the eggs.
Pour the lemon juice
inside.
Some of the broth
that's inside the cabbage.
Okay, then I'm gonna
add some flour.
Just to tighten it up
a bit.
Then pour it in.
Nice.
Then I swirl it around
a little bit,
and now they are ready.
Beautiful.
Oh.
Oh, those are so good.
The lemon sauce
is outstanding.
The cabbage is not so tender
that it's falling apart,
so it's got a little bit
of its own texture.
Not too much rice.
And a little bit
of the mint,
little of the dill.
I'm gonna tell you
something, girl.
Those are delicious.
Dolmades.
MAN: Fabulous.
It's one of my favorites.
Real lemony taste to it.
This is very light
and very tasty.
MAN:
All the food is really good,
and the desserts
are even better.
FIERI: This work over here
with the pastries and all that.
That's the --
That's the specialty work.
That's my baby.
And where did you learn
to make pastries?
My mom was a great baker,
and as a little girl,
I learned how to bake.
FIERI: From baked goods
to hearty entrées,
there's something
for everyone here.
Braised beef on pasta.
Braised beef over pasta?
Yes.
It's something that you
will eat in a Greek home.
I've never seen it
on a Greek menu.
Okay.
We're gonna start out
with tri-tip.
I'm going to season this.
With...?
Our secret.
So, we can say
kind of a seasoned salt.
With some oregano,
onion powder...
I like it.
Put some olive oil
in my pot.
Diced onions.
Gonna put the meat in there.
Fresh diced tomatoes.
Tomato sauce.
And I'm gonna use
this little gadget I have.
This is where things are
gonna get interesting.
Put my cinnamon stick
and my cloves.
I like this.
Kitchen Bouquet for color.
Water to cover this up.
This is gonna go at a low
simmer for about two hours.
The pasta's ready.
This is a Greek-style pasta.
It looks like bucatini.
It's got the nice hole
in the middle of it.
Now we're gonna add
some butter to this.
This is Mizithra.
Mizithra.
Greek Parmesan.
Exactly.
Is it sheep's cheese?
Yes.
We like to give
big portions.
Holy moly.
And there you go.
Mmm.
The beef is nice and tender.
Tri-tip is a great piece
of meat to use in this --
lot of fat,
lot of flavor in that.
The tomatoes --
You definitely get that.
But what makes it
a little bit different
is that little added kick --
cinnamon and clove.
The pasta's fantastic.
It's a great dish,
very comforting,
made with a lot of love
and a lot of care.
Excellent.
It's fabulous.
The meat is perfect.
Savory flavors.
The seasoning was excellent.
MAN: One of the best
restaurants,
period, in Bakersfield.
Period?
Period.
If this is what Greece is about,
I want to go.
You treat this
like your house.
I do.
It really feels it.
I treat my guests
like my family.
Aww, huh?
You're gonna love this girl.
Come down and try this.
Coming up, we're sticking
around Bakersfield...
Outstanding.
...for an old-school landmark...
It feels like I'm in an old
Basque restaurant because I am.
...firing up a full-on
cultural feast.
So, I can eat as much
of that as I want?
Oh, yeah.
[ Train horn blows ]
Now, you know on "Triple D,"
I love finding the old-school
joints,
and, boy, do I have one
for you -- a joint from 1901.
So, here I am on the east side
of Bakersfield, California,
right by
the Southern Pacific Railroad.
Now, from 1901 to 1935,
this place was a lot
of different joints.
But since 1935, everybody
in Bakersfield knows this place.
This is the Pyrenees Café.
Pyrenees is a landmark.
The food here is incredible.
Good flavors made from scratch
right from home.
FIERI: And right from
the Basque tradition.
Osso buco up.
FIERI: This old-world menu has
been a long-time staple here,
so when Julie and Ron Crawford
took over in 2014,
they weren't about
to change it.
Basque food -- Is it hard
to explain that
to people in Bakersfield?
No. Everybody
in Bakersfield gets it.
It's hard to explain
to the rest of the world.
MAN: Traditionally, it is
ethnic food that comes
from the Basque region
between France and Spain.
And French-born chef
Gilbert Hernandez
knows a thing or two
about the Basque people.
It was the best
sheep herders.
The best sheep herders.
Oh, yeah.
People would ask the Basque
to come to the United States
to raise sheep.
These are poor people...
Yes, exactly.
...living in the hills.
Yes. With nothing they
used to make a meal.
So, they have to become
creative.
And they use every part
of the animal.
Yes.
MAN: You can get everything
from the pickled tongue
to soup or whatever the specials
are for the day.
Fried chicken ready.
They're the best at it.
It's really kind of a mainstay.
MAN: And it's not
Southern fried chicken
by any stretch
of the imagination.
And I think the garlic just
makes it something different.
So, what are we
gonna make today, Chef?
Fried garlic chicken.
We're gonna fry the garlic
or we're gonna fry the chicken?
We're gonna fry
the chicken.
Okay, let's go do it.
All right.
Little chickens.
Yes.
You see he just takes
the knife right through,
no question
of where the joint is.
That was a no-looky.
[ Chuckles ]
Now you're showing off.
Now we're gonna season
the chicken.
Salt, black pepper,
garlic powder,
chicken base.
And then we're gonna
put some fresh garlic.
Okay.
Lot of garlic.
Bit of olive oil?
Yes.
You're welcome.
There we go.
Perfect.
Now, how long are we gonna
let this marinate, Chef?
At least two hours.
At least two hours?
Yes.
Then after, we're gonna
put some buttermilk.
And then after,
we dredge it in flour --
seasoning flour --
black pepper and salt.
That's it?
That's it.
But we're not going
to the fryer.
We're going to this?
Yes.
This is the Basque way
of doing it,
because nobody in
the Pyrenees Mountains had --
Exactly.
Okay.
No, no.
I like how he just takes
his time, just nice and easy.
And how long do we cook it?
15, 20 minutes.
FIERI: And what comes
with this, Chef?
This comes with the green beans
and french fries.
Here's the chicken.
Very nice.
What's in the garlic sauce?
Fresh garlic with olive oil
and a little bit
of butter and parsley.
And here is your
Basque garlic chicken.
The garlic on the outside
is very strong,
but the garlic and the flavor
inside in the chicken
is what is really nice.
It's tender, it's juicy,
lots of flavor.
The crust on the chicken
is great.
I have restaurants
called Johnny Garlic's.
Uh-huh.
I have one in Bakersfield,
but if I was gonna ever
make fried garlic chicken,
that would be the example.
Outstanding.
The garlic just
hits you right away
as soon as you bite into it.
Probably don't want to have your
first date after you eat it,
but it's very, very good.
The best chicken
that you'll ever have.
FIERI: Even though it's rooted
in humble beginnings...
MAN:
Basque food is peasant food.
Cuts of meat nobody wanted,
and you had to figure out a way
to make those meats
flavorful and tasteful.
How close is this to
traditional,
original Basque
like you get at home?
Probably a little better
than what we had at home.
[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: And just like home,
they're rocking it family style.
Let me ask you this.
On the menu, I see
the Basque meal.
The Set-up. Yes.
The Set-up.
Four courses.
I want to try that.
You get a Basque soup,
beans, a tongue, salad.
What is the entrée?
What is the finale?
Oxtail stew.
Oxtail stew?
Yes.
I want oxtail stew.
Here's the deal.
We're hanging out in Bakersfield
at the Pyrenees Café.
When you come back,
the chef's gonna give me
something called the Set-up.
Yes.
See you in a bit.
So, here we are
at the Pyrenees Café
in Bakersfield, California,
hanging out
with Chef Gilbert.
Now, this guy has worked
at this restaurant
for 300 years.
[ Laughs ]
No, 30 years on and off,
and he is the head chef
here now.
So, we had some fantastic
garlic chicken,
but now he's gonna make me
something called the what?
Oxtail stew.
In the Set-up.
FIERI: Also known as four
courses of family-style fixin's
with individual entrées
like the one I'm going with.
Oxtail stew is a classic.
MAN: Because it's such
a tough cut of meat,
it has to be cooked
for hours in its own juices,
and it comes out fantastic.
Okay, let's start
with oxtail stew.
Now, is that really
from an ox,
or is it just from beef?
From beef.
[ Whistles ]
Haven't quite seen the tail
just in its...tail form
in a while.
What are we gonna marinate
this in?
Lime juice.
And brandy.
I thought the brandy
was for us.
So, we're gonna cook this
on the stove.
Yes.
For how long?
At least 25 minutes.
Till it browns up?
Yes.
And now we're going to...
Deglaze with red wine.
Gonna let them simmer
a little bit,
and then we're gonna
add a little bit of sage.
A little bit?
Ooh!
Italian seasoning.
Hot chili pepper.
The garlic.
Oregano.
Salt.
Paprika.
Italian seasoning.
Again?
The first one
was a powder.
This one is crushed.
Cumin.
Tomato paste.
Yes.
And black pepper.
Beef broth.
Beef broth that you made?
Yes.
Now we are ready to add
the potatoes,
celery, and carrots.
And then, when
that's cooked, we serve it.
Exactly.
FIERI: Which means it's time
for the owner, Julie,
to help guide me
through this mega meal.
Okay. So,
the oxtail stew is done.
Yes.
You come in
and have the Set-up,
this is what you get.
What's the first course?
The beans and the salsa
and the Basque vegetable soup.
So, I can eat as much
of that as I want?
Oh, yeah.
And now you help yourself
to the salad
and pickled tongue
and cottage cheese.
Cottage cheese, cucumbers,
pickled tongue.
Not a huge, huge tongue fan.
When in Rome...
That's some
really good tongue.
You make the tongue, too?
Oh, yes, I do.
There's such a variety.
All the senses are hitting --
warm food, cold food,
spicy food.
I'm done with this.
They take it away.
And now I get...
French fries,
spaghetti.
I've had a lot
of Basque food.
I don't know that I've ever had
spaghetti in it.
I can't eat any more.
[ Chuckles ]
What?!
Okay, and now we've got
your oxtail stew here.
FIERI: Look at that.
Oh, that's good.
Mmm.
It is tender. It's meaty.
Forget about it.
Mmm.
All right.
Wrap that all up to go.
[ Both laugh ]
Oxtail stew up!
Delicious,
tender, tasty.
For a family to come here
and eat like this --
I mean, look at the spread.
Tons of food.
It's just a place that
I'm drawn to constantly.
FIERI: If I lived in this town,
this would be a place
that I would visit
at least once a week.
I mean, it feels like
I'm in an old Basque restaurant
'cause I am.
Uh-huh.
And the food matches.
It's delicious.
Wonderful job.
Thank you.
Up next, we're cruising over
to Taft, California...
Here we go.
...to a place killing it
with their pad Thai...
Tell me that
does not look good.
...and this soup making me
come back for seconds.
If I could just get it
in a cup and drink it.
That's how good it is.
So, we're shooting
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
over in Bakersfield, California,
about 45 minutes away,
and I come here to Taft
to visit some friends.
And they say, "Hey, Guy,
let's take you out to dinner.
We got a great place."
After my first bite,
I knew this joint had to be
on "Triple D."
This is Asian Experience.
And I have the Siamese
sweet and sour.
It's absolutely the best
Thai food I've ever had.
WOMAN: Garlic chicken delight,
please.
Hold on to your socks.
You're not gonna expect it.
Really awesome.
It is awesome.
You can't wait to dig in because
it's just so interesting.
These are my buddies
the Morrises and the Houses.
They tell me that they've got
this place
that they want to take me to
for dinner.
Out comes the food,
and I didn't say anything
because I was inhaling the soup.
I think I had
about five portions.
You had a little bit
of everything.
Don't tell them.
Don't tell them how much I ate.
The food is great, but I really
do think it's the people here.
Dennis and Niki
sell the whole place.
The Dennis show is on
all the time.
FIERI: We're talking about
local native Dennis Schertz
and his Thai-born wife, Niki,
who decided to share the food
they love
with the town they love
in '06.
As opposed
to going just Thai,
you said this is
an Asian experience --
a real Asian experience.
True.
Exciting food with flavors
you don't have every day.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
It's got to be the pad Thai.
Pad Thai, please.
All right, Niki.
What are we gonna make first?
Gonna make
the tamarind sauce for pad Thai.
For the pad Thai noodles.
Yes. Just like that.
What's this
cooking in the back?
This is pork and salt
and a little bit of soup base
for making broth.
Pork, salt, and chicken base.
Okay.
That's tamarind paste?
Yes.
Sugar, like this.
There you go.
And a little bit of salt.
Paprika.
And you cook like this
for three hours.
Good.
So, now we've got
our tamarind sauce.
The wok is hot?
Yes. Hot.
Let's do it.
Gonna put oil...
Sweet radish.
Sweet radish and garlic.
Yep.
And pork.
And that's it
for the pork?
Yep. Gonna put noodle.
Right in like that?
Yes.
Just like that.
And the tamarind sauce
goes right in.
So, all the flavors that
are developing in there
are gonna rehydrate
the noodles.
Yep. You like spicy?
I can put --
Yeah, I like spicy.
Yeah.
Aah!
That is good.
Is that how much
I got last time?
Yes.
Did you eat that spicy?
I was sweating.
I'm gonna put a little bit
of broth so it not burn.
Dennis says when he's
in trouble,
you make his food
very spicy.
Yes. Just like that.
Just punishing.
Punishing.
Yes.
Tell me that
does not look good.
There's even egg in the dish,
and I'm eating it.
You know it's
got to be good.
[ Chuckles ]
Gonna throw this --
bean sprout and onions.
Then we're done.
Gonna put it on the plate.
Okay.
And also the peanut.
Too spicy?
For me?
[ Mouths ]
Nah.
The tamarind sauce...
Yes.
...that's really what gets
the whole party started.
Little sweet there,
crunchy peanut,
you get a touch of the, uh,
chili flake coming through.
I love that the noodles
are really al dente.
It's authentic.
You make it just like
you make for your family?
Yes. My family like it like
this, and my mom cook like this.
That's it.
Cooking is fun.
You're fun, Niki.
Huh?
I tell you or what?
Real deal.
WOMAN:
I have the pad Thai right here.
MAN: Delicious.
It's rich.
It's got great meat
and spice flavors to it.
It's just noodle heaven.
This is my buddy Eli.
Eli watches the Food Network
all the time.
What were you and I eating
when we sat at this table?
What did you order?
Tofu.
It's the bomb.
Dig that.
And dig this -- Niki's
laying down everything
from fried rice
in a pineapple...
Which is great.
...to a dish with a name
that tells it like it is.
Garlic delight with chicken.
MAN:
Lots of garlic, lots of flavor,
and it's just hard to beat.
FIERI: And, of course,
the one
that kicked it off for me
the last time.
I have the tom yum goong
right here.
It's a sweet, spicy, sour soup.
This is tom yum...
Goong.
I've had it good.
This was great.
Here we go.
We're gonna start
from soup base.
[ Sizzles ]
A little too hot.
I think the pot
was hot, Niki.
Yes.
The chicken stock, the salt,
pork, water mixture.
So, what we have here, just so
everybody can see this --
lemongrass, Kaffir lime leaf,
and galangal root.
So, galangal is kind of
like a mild ginger.
Yes.
Okay, now I pour in this one.
Tomatoes, chopped.
Chili paste.
You can buy anywhere.
Which kind of chili paste?
Shrimp.
Shrimp chili paste.
Yes. We're gonna
let them boiling
until we smell
all the herbs in there.
Waking up.
Everything's gonna wake up.
Salt -- just pinch.
Put the mushroom.
And the shrimp.
Yeah.
[ Whistles ]
Big meal for me.
Lemon juice?
Lemon juice.
The shrimp start pink...
As soon as they start
turning pink...
...turn it off.
Now we should pour it.
Now evaporated milk.
Evaporated milk. Okay.
And a little bit
of cilantro.
Yep.
Now you can taste it.
[ Slurps ]
Oh!
I can't even tell you
how good this is.
This is nice and light
and bright and fresh
and a little bit spicy.
Galangal is the key.
Yes.
Like, if I could just get it
in a cup and drink it.
That's how good it is.
I'm not kidding you.
I'm starting to sweat.
I'm not enjoying it at all.
That's just a delicious flavor.
Everything you could
possibly want in a bowl.
After coming here a few times,
I knew I was hooked.
It is the best food in town.
Probably one of the best Asian
experiences I've ever had.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
Really outstanding.
Get in your car -- You need to
take the family on a road trip.
Come on out to Taft.
Bring the kids.
You're the best.
Thank you so much.
I love this girl,
I'll tell you what.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I got one for you.
You're gonna love it.
So, I was
in Bakersfield, California,
with 45--
I'm in a food coma
is what I'm in.
So, I'm here in...
[ Laughs ]