Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
You want to get in
on some of this?
Absolutely.
Things are getting meaty
in Flavortown...
There's nothing about that
I don't love.
...on the grill, in the smoker,
and all 'cued up.
Have you had this?
In Los Angeles, California...
♪ Oh, whee, oh ♪
...a little spot firing up
big flavor...
Off the hook.
...with specialties
straight from the Yucatán.
You learn something new
every day, baby.
In Las Vegas, Nevada...
This is pizza Picasso.
...a legit
east-coast pizzeria...
Throw it in there!
...mixing barbecue
into the bada bing.
Who says?
I say.
And if we're in Vegas...
Ouch!
...you know we got to check out
my joint...
You guys got to come meet
this cat.
...and some smoking secrets
stacked into the sandwich.
It's got to have
the Motley Cue attitude.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
I'm here in Los Angeles,
just a few blocks from USC,
to check out
a funky, little joint
that's housed here
in the Mercado La Paloma.
It's an economic-development
building.
Now, they've got a family
in here from the Yucatán
that is serving up legit,
real-deal Mexican food
that you probably
haven't seen before.
This is Chichén Itza.
CETINA: Order up.
Chochinita Pibil, table four.
Chichén Itza's food is amazing.
Pollo asado.
MAN:
Out of control, man.
Outrageous?
Full-on flavor explosion.
We got an order up
for table six.
They have taken the Yucatán
and brought the food,
the spices,
the taste, the texture here.
FIERI:
That's exactly the tradition
Chef Gilberto Cetina Jr.
wanted to preserve.
This is the food
that I grew up with.
This is what my grandma
used to cook.
This is what my mom used to cook
growing up in Yucatán.
I love it, man.
And so do his customers
ever since his dad
opened the joint in 2001.
This is very
labor-intensive food.
You can taste it.
Longaniza asada.
So, the longaniza is like
a chorizo sausage link.
It's full of flavor.
What are we gonna make?
The longaniza asada.
Longaniza asada.
Very traditional
Yucatán style.
We're gonna start
with pork shoulder,
ground fat,
and ground beef.
Next?
Oregano.
Garlic powder.
Clove.
Onion.
Then we're gonna add
some vinegar.
Salt and...
Cumin.
Got it.
Mix this all by hand.
And then we're gonna add
the achiote paste.
Oh, ho-ho, hey.
Not going light
with that, huh?
About 4 ounces.
This is what gives
the great color
to a lot of Latin food.
All right, so,
the casing goes on.
Natural sheep casing.
Anchor down.
Oh, nice and thin.
Yeah.
♪ Oh, whee, oh ♪
♪ Ohh, oh ♪
Perfect.
Now we're gonna link 'em.
Now,
how are we gonna smoke 'em?
We're gonna hang 'em
on a stainless-steel dowel
over embers.
They're gonna sit there
overnight.
A little bit of heat,
little bit of smoke.
Then we're gonna
grill these.
Here is the sausage
after being smoked and grilled.
Serve it with some tortillas,
fire-roasted onions,
and then fire-roasted salsa.
So, everything on here
was cooked on that same grill.
There is nothing about that
I don't love.
It's a Yucatán hot dog.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm.
A little bit of salt,
touch of spice,
great meat-to-fat ratio.
Definitely get the wood
and the smoke.
That's fantastic.
Thank you.
Longaniza asada.
This is excellent.
MAN:
Just intense flavor --
something different
like I've never had before.
Panuchos.
Super authentic,
really authentic.
We're half Hispanic,
so this tastes just like
my grandma makes.
I love it.
This is also
a great community space.
There's other small,
locally owned businesses.
FIERI:
All centered around a main
eating and hangout space.
MAN: I come here
to be able to spend my dollar
with really awesome
mom-and-pop shops --
a lot of really
indigenous recipes.
So, what's the next dish?
Panucho.
WOMAN: Panuchos.
It's one of my favorites,
and I always order them.
FIERI: And I'm sticking around
to try 'em.
Wow!
Coming up next.
Oh, my gosh!
All right, so,
we're back
at Chichén Itza
here in Los Angeles,
and I got to
tell you something.
It's taken me
that much time to recover
from the fantastic
longaniza asada.
FIERI:
Which is just the start
of a long list
of real-deal dishes
straight from the Yucatán.
It's very unique.
I mean, it's not your typical
Mexican-food restaurant.
FIERI: Have you ever had
Yucatán food?
No.
This is like
a free plane ticket.
Absolutely.
It's a very different twist.
I wouldn't necessarily
call that Mexican food
if you just sat it down
in front of me.
Say it has
its own personality.
Order up, table 12!
The combinations
are so delightful.
MAN: And they have
a really awesome modern spin
on some really ancient dishes.
Panuchos.
It's kind of like a tostada.
But it's infused
with black-bean paste.
And it's delicious.
All right,
what do we do with this turkey?
We're gonna boil the legs,
and we're gonna sous-vide
the breast.
'Cause that's what you see
every day
in a little kiosk Yucatán joint
here in Los Angeles.
To cook the legs in a stock pot,
we put water...
salt,
garlic, oregano.
Okay.
Bay leaves...
black pepper...cilantro...
wings...
legs and thighs.
Like a little
court bouillon.
Exactly.
Now we're gonna prepare
the turkey breast
for its sous-vide cooking.
Let's get into this.
Kosher salt, both sides.
Take a sous-vide bag.
A little bit of cilantro
in there.
And this is it
for the seasoning.
That's it.
We're gonna vacuum this?
We are.
Okay.
150 degrees?
Yeah.
How long?
2 1/2 hours.
Got it.
This is not boiling.
This is simmering,
but it's precise.
Now, the beauty
about sous-vide is,
you can go
for long periods of time --
and we're talking days --
to where it's so tender
that when you open it
out of the bag,
it'll just fall apart.
So, we're gonna make
the tortillas now
for the panuchos.
[ Spanish accent ]
Tortillas.
So, we're gonna make
little balls of masa.
In it goes.
[ Normal voice ] So, why is this
going to puff up open?
Mine don't often puff up.
Once both layers
are cooked evenly,
you press down
on the tortilla.
It generates steam
and puffs up.
And there it is.
You learn something new
every day, baby.
Okay.
Open it up.
Some black-bean puree.
Okay.
Cover the hole.
You spread it out.
Love it.
Now we're gonna fry 'em.
Double-cooked tortilla.
All right,
here we are, Chef.
All right, so, we're gonna make
the achiote marinade
to paint our turkeys.
Paint our turkeys.
And put 'em on the grill.
All right, so, we're gonna start
with some achiote paste
and then fresh,
sour oranges.
I love it.
Some salt.
Now we're gonna paint
the turkey.
Beautiful color
going in here,
and they're gonna go
on the grill.
Yeah.
Then we're gonna shred
the meat off of the turkey?
Right.
Which part is the panucho?
This is the panucho.
That's the panucho.
This is
the traditional panucho.
This is what you would get
if you go eat at a market
or mercado in Yucatán.
Little bit of lettuce.
Some of the shredded leg
and sous-vide breast.
Some pickled red onions,
tomato.
And a slice of avocado.
And that's all she wrote?
That is the panucho.
Man!
It's so tender, delicious.
Really simple,
but done correctly.
I've had a lot of tacos.
I really appreciate
Mexican food.
It's subtle.
It's authentic.
That's a nostalgic dish.
Oh, my gosh!
Panuchos.
This is a very delightful
and complex dish.
What is your favorite thing
about these tacos?
Well, I really like
how it's crunchy,
but the avocado gives it
a wet texture at the same time.
[ Laughter ]
Order up, table four!
WOMAN: I know I will never
be disappointed.
I love their food.
Authentic, baby.
Real deal.
Thank you.
Off the hook.
FIERI: Coming up
in Las Vegas, Nevada...
It's gorgeous pie.
A pizzeria betting
on their barbecue...
You're a pizza joint.
Yeah, but we got
to be different.
...and winning big on Philly.
I've eaten
a lot of cheesesteaks.
I've never seen
this pepper game going on.
So, here I am,
about 15 miles west of the Strip
in Las Vegas, Nevada,
in an area known as The Lakes,
and what do you get up here?
Well, you get really nice cars,
you get really nice houses,
and, of course, you'd expect
to find two dudes from Jersey
and one from California that
are serving up great pizza.
This is Those Guys Pies.
Italian white up in the window!
The best pizza by far
in Las Vegas.
All right, your Greek pie.
It stands up there with some of
the best pizza in New York.
FIERI:
That's because behind the pie
are two Jersey transplants,
Roy Bass and Colin O'Leary,
who wanted to bring a big taste
of their childhood out west.
I found somebody as passionate
about pizza as me,
and we decided
to start a business.
Top it off
with co-owner Chris Builder,
and in 2012,
Vegas got Those Guys.
18-inch cheese up in the window!
How close is this to real-deal,
old-school, east-coast pizza?
Off the charts.
But Roy's not afraid to break
tradition on his toppings.
Barbecue maui wowi
in the window!
Pork, jalapeños, pineapple,
barbecue sauce.
Every ingredient
complements each other.
FIERI:
Let's get into this.
We're gonna start making
our barbecue rub.
Brown sugar...
smoked paprika...
kosher salt.
Okay.
A little bit of cinnamon...
cayenne pepper...
garlic...
crushed red pepper...
granulated onion...
and coarse ground pepper.
Mix this all up together.
Yeah.
Rub the pork butt.
Put it in a walk-in
for about 24 hours.
Okay, then to the smoker.
Yeah.
How many hours was that?
16.
We're gonna do
a little shred on it.
Now we're gonna season
our pork.
We make
a house-pickled jalapeño.
We're gonna take
some of that juice
from our pickling jalapeño
and put that on there.
What are we making now?
House-made barbecue sauce.
You're a pizza joint.
Yeah, but we got
to be different.
All right.
We're gonna start
with bacon...
some garlic...
onions.
Okay, so, it renders down.
So, then we're gonna use
a little bit of liquid smoke,
vinegar.
Some brown sugar...
little bit of Dijon mustard.
"Little bit"?
We got the honey,
and then molasses.
Molasses.
Yes.
Chili sauce...
a little bit of ketchup.
Busy guy.
And then, boom, black pepper.
So, this cooks down...
For about 35 minutes.
All right,
gonna make the maui wowi.
I got to wear this
to the prom later.
I won't get you dirty,
I promise, okay?
That's big skin, man.
What size pie is this?
This is gonna be
an 18-inch pie.
Barbecue sauce
mixed with pizza sauce.
Yes, 50/50.
This is pizza Picasso.
Whole-milk mozzarella.
Pulled pork that we smoke.
Now we're gonna do
house bacon.
So you cure
your own bacon?
Yes, sir.
Never can be too much pork
in a pizzeria.
We got fresh pineapple.
You get caught from
your friends on the east coast
putting pineapple
on a pizza...
We're gonna get
a couple e-mails.
Then our own jalapeños.
We're gonna finish it
just...
with a little sprinkle
of cheese.
What temperature
is the oven at?
550.
Can we throw it in the oven?
Throw it in there!
That's right!
9, 10 minutes.
[ Whistles ]
We're gonna add a little bit
of cilantro to it.
It's a gorgeous pie.
This is legit pizza, man.
It doesn't taste
like barbecue sauce.
You don't get lost
in that.
It's like smoky,
bacon-y tomato sauce.
The jalapeños are spot-on.
The crust is fantastic.
Just get a couple
of those little sweet bites
out of the pineapple.
Smoking in the pork,
making your own ingredients,
making your own sauces --
I would drive up to The Lakes
just to get this.
Appreciate that.
Thank you.
All right,
we got your barbecue maui wowi.
Has the perfect combination
of salty, sweet, and spicy.
One of my ways to find out
if you've got really good pizza
is to talk to one of
my ATO fraternity brothers.
We've had some bad pizza
in our day.
Horrible.
How would this have done?
This is fantastic.
A pie like this,
you got to drive
across town.
It's a small place
that's off the beaten path,
kind of hard to find.
It's one of those
places you hear about,
word gets around.
It's just this little
hidden gem.
What else do you like
on the menu?
Best cheesesteak around.
Works cheesesteak
up in the window!
It's like
going back to Philly.
Absolutely.
We're gonna do
a pickled green pepper
for our steak sandwich
because the green pepper
can't just be a green pepper.
Who says?
I say.
Okay.
Those Guys say.
So, we got rice wine vinegar,
cider vinegar.
Sugar and salt.
Brown sugar.
Garlic, onion,
and 3 gallons of water.
I've eaten
a lot of cheesesteaks.
I've never seen
this pepper game going on.
That's why our cheesesteaks
are a unique cheesesteak.
And we're gonna put
the peppers inside here
and pour everything in there
and put it in the walk-in.
Okay, let's do it.
We're gonna start with
a nice little handful of onions,
and we got green peppers.
And then a little bit
of mushroom.
This is rib-eye?
This is rib-eye.
We're gonna do a little
seasoning on this meat.
We're only making
one sandwich.
I don't like people
to leave my store hungry.
Chop it up nice and fine.
Do you see the technique
where he's holding the one out
and bringing this one down?
It's gangster.
All right.
We're almost there.
White American cheese.
White American --
nice, four big slices.
You ready for this?
I'm gonna fold that cheese
inside of the sandwich.
Yeah.
This is -- Whoa, I don't want
to take you out, Guy.
Boom.
I do like that --
the cheese tucked away.
You want to get in
on some of this?
Oh, absolutely, sir.
Absolutely.
Ready?
Mmm.
I like how you tucked
the cheese into bed
and that meat --
nice medium-rare.
That's one of the most legit
I've had in a while,
but you know
what the kicker is?
It's the acid
of that green bell pepper.
It's what takes it
to the next level.
Had a lot of other cheesesteaks
here in town,
but nobody compares
to what they put out here.
WOMAN:
Your works cheesesteak.
MAN:
You just close your eyes.
You'll think you're back
on the Jersey Shore.
I got a meatball coming out!
Probably my favorite
place to eat here in Vegas.
FIERI:
This is the kind of joint
that when people watch
"Triple D," they go,
"I don't even know
how to get to The Lakes,
but get me a cab off the Strip.
I want to go see that joint."
Nice job, guys.
Congratulations.
FIERI: Up next,
we're headed to the Strip...
All right.
I like where this is going.
...for a crazy look
at my joint...
Take us down the road,
Chef.
...back in the kitchen...
We've taken the Vegas fries
to another level.
...and behind the bar.
This is exactly what you need
after a rough night in Vegas.
Welcome back, Mr. Fieri.
Thank you.
Listen,
if you would've ever told me
that I was gonna be
on the Food Network,
I'd say you're crazy.
And if you ever told me
I was gonna come back
to Las Vegas
and open my own restaurant
on the Strip,
I'd say you're out of your mind,
so I guess that makes you
crazy and out of your mind?
'Cause I'm here
at The Linq Hotel & Casino
to check out my joint.
This is
Guy's Vegas Kitchen + Bar.
Pick it up, sashimi won tacos!
It's unbelievable.
WOMAN: All right,
bacon mac-and-cheese burger.
It reminds me of Guy --
a lot of energy going on here.
WOMAN: Kind of goes
with the flow of Vegas --
super-good vibe, fun.
So, now it's time
to meet the cat
that came up with
all the crazy ideas.
Chef, come on in, please.
So, Chef, tell me,
what was the inspiration
behind Guy's Vegas?
Going to college
in Las Vegas,
always coming down
to the Strip,
I always just thought about
having a cool, little,
funky joint that served
just righteous food.
You felt comfortable
coming back multiple times.
That's what we made here.
But with all my time
on the road,
you know I need a solid team
to back me up,
and I got that,
led by Chef Tony Leitera.
Number-one-selling item
on the menu is...
Mac-and-cheese burger.
The number-two
best-selling sandwich?
Motley Cue.
Here, we have
the Motley Cue sandwich.
Watching this pulled-pork
sandwich come out,
my mouth was watering.
Take us down the road, Chef.
We got our Danish collar
pork butt.
We're gonna make
the rub for it right now.
This is our brown sugar...
kosher salt,
garlic, cayenne.
Paprika.
We got our chili,
brown cloves,
black pepper,
a little bit of nutmeg.
When you name it after
your barbecue team, Motley Cue,
it's got to have
the Motley Cue attitude.
All right, so,
we're gonna dry-rub this.
Now, when you walk
into this restaurant,
you're thinking, "Okay,
where's the big smoker?
Why don't I smell it?"
Because it's in the basement.
So, we're gonna let this go
for 12 hours.
Set 220.
Yeah.
The pork butt's done.
Okay,
you look at all that bark,
all that great smoked flavor,
and it's super tender.
Drop it in a little bit
of that pan dripping.
Now, the other
great thing is,
we have this pretzel roll
made for us.
We're gonna cut this
in half.
It's got to have
a little garlic butter
just to add
that extra bit of flavor,
but you got to put
a little crust
on the outside of this.
So, you're gonna
toast that off?
Yeah.
Next up.
We got
our toasted bun here.
We're gonna start
with our donkey sauce.
It's a combination
of a little mustard,
a little mayonnaise,
a little Worcestershire,
a little black pepper,
a little garlic.
So, next,
we're gonna melt the cheese.
Cheddar.
Okay.
First thing's first --
pickles.
We got our citrus slaw.
And then we got our pork.
Then we're gonna
garnish it up
with a little bit
of my barbecue sauce.
Bourbon/brown sugar
barbecue sauce,
and a touch of the Carolina
just to add a little bit
of that vinegar flavor.
The two together --
perfect.
We don't do
just one kind of fry.
This is how the fries
get served up every time.
Shoestring, crinkle cut,
sidewinder,
and everybody loves
a waffle, right?
Chef, go ahead
and jump in on that.
Mmm!
Great smoke,
a little bit of the sweet,
a little bit of the vinegar.
The crunch of the slaw,
a little bit
of that acid coming through,
pickles --
you got to have the pickles --
and then this nice pretzel bun
with the little leathery skin
on the outside -- very nice.
WOMAN:
And your Motley Cue sandwich.
Absolutely tender and delicious.
You get the sweet
and the salty with it.
It's really good.
This is Dan Geraldo, one
of my roommates from college.
This is typical
Guy Fieri food.
This is what you used to do
when we roomed,
and I would just be amazed.
This is Professor
John Stefanelli.
He's a professor at UNLV.
I had him
for all kinds of classes.
How do you think we're doing?
The food is great
because it's you.
It's definitely you.
FIERI: Which means I put
plenty on the menu
"Triple D"-style
that you don't need a fork
and knife to dig into.
The fireball whiskey wings.
What do you think
of the wings?
They're just incredible.
Good crunch in the wing?
Yeah, definitely.
Here, we have
the Vegas fries for you.
Bleu cheese crumbled on top,
and then you can spread
a little buffalo sauce over it.
Best fries I've ever had.
We've taken the Vegas fries
to another level.
So, what we have here,
they're sidewinder fries...
Frank's hot sauce powder.
Now we just give them a little
spritz of the wing sauce.
Okay, a little bit
of bleu cheese.
Yeah.
Just top it off with a little
carrots and celery.
This is our Frank's and butter
and bleu-sabi sauce.
Give this a nice little bath
of the wing sauce.
Nice butter, vinegar,
cayenne pepper.
Little dip
in the bleu-sabi bleu.
Mmm!
It's crunchy.
It's tangy.
It's totally buffalo.
Well done, man.
Here, we have the Vegas fries.
Love it.
The sauces are good.
The one is spicy,
and then the other one
cools it down a little bit,
so if you mix them up,
they're just perfect.
It screams,
"I want a big beer."
FIERI: And if that
doesn't do the trick,
well, we got to kick it up
a notch.
WOMAN:
Guy's Bloody Mary for you.
I love a good Bloody Mary,
and this is everything
that I could ask for.
Kick this off, man.
Start it out right --
jalapeños.
Ouch!
Fresnos.
Now, don't worry.
This isn't
that super spicy hot,
well, until the garlic
gets in there.
Fresh garlic.
Okay.
Tomato juice.
And then we're gonna start
to whisk it.
A little bit
of barbecue sauce.
One of each of our barbecues.
Nice smoky flavor
coming out of that.
All right.
I like where this is going.
Hot sauce,
a little bit more hot sauce.
A little bit of Worcester --
Worcestershire.
[ Mumbling ]
Worcester-sher-shire.
A little bit of salt.
Now, we're gonna let this set up
for about an hour.
About an hour.
Fantastic.
Vodka, my brother.
There we go.
Okay.
This is the Bloody Mary.
Now, we've strained this.
Gonna finish it off
with some candied bacon,
apple sausage,
Italian-imported pepperoni,
fresh veggies,
a little bit more jalapeño.
Straws.
This is exactly what you need
after a rough night in Vegas.
[ Sighs ]
That'll do the trick.
WOMAN:
Guy's Bloody Mary!
I love spice,
so it tastes really good.
Dessert tickets --
s'mores Monte Cristo.
Highly recommended
to anybody coming to Vegas.
Chef Tony...
you da man.
You guys got to come meet
this cat.
So, that's it for this
Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
This is about the weirdest
interview I've ever had.
Come on.
Let's go.
[ Laughter ]