Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoa! Whoa-oh!
...we're hitting
the highway...
We're rolling
right along here.
right along.
...for a righteous
cross-country road trip.
It's gonna
change your life.
It's gonna change my waistband,
is what it's gonna change.
First, it's Somers Point,
New Jersey...
This is awesome.
...a local legend
dishing out hearty favorites...
Don't give small portions here,
do you, boss?
...with a heapin' helpin'
of history.
That is about as
old-school legit as they come.
Then
in Gilbert, Arizona...
Oh!
...a paisano pizzeria
going big...
This is a pizza
that eats like a dinner.
...serving up Sicily
to the Southwest.
I know everybody in Italy
thinks you're crazy.
I like crazy people.
And in Bakersfield,
California...
Giddyup.
...a barbecue stop
bringing in business...
[ Whistles ]
Good-looking bird.
...by sending up the smoke
street-side.
Oh.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So, I'm here
at Somers Point, New Jersey,
right on Bay Avenue
to check out a joint
that's got a lot of history.
Let's see. It started out
as a hotel back in the '70s.
That's the 1870s.
Well, then they were known
for their 7-for-1 beers,
the big fire of '06 --
well, that was 2006 --
and now, well,
they're known for everything
except their lamb dishes.
This is The Anchorage Tavern.
Two buffalo crab cakes
going up.
Lots of different dishes.
WAITRESS:
White clam dinner.
This is truly
the landmark of Somers Point.
Everybody knows The Anchorage.
Everything's fresh, and that's
the way Don likes to do it here.
Thank you.
FIERI: That's chef and owner
Don Mahoney,
who took over
this local institution in 1997.
The recipes were already here
or you developed them?
No. We made the whole menu.
They're all my favorites.
You'll see
there's no lamb on the menu.
Do people come in
and ask for lamb?
No. They know
I don't like it.
Oh, okay.
Hey, come on down
and try the lamb special.
MAN:
The way Don runs this place,
it could be around
for 100 years more.
WOMAN:
All the seafood's wonderful.
Flounder Gorgonzola
in the window.
I love the flounder.
It's nice and flaky.
Crabmeat filling is excellent.
It's an outstanding dish.
All right,
what are we into, boss?
We're making crab stuffing,
okay?
We're gonna stuff some
really nice flounder with this.
We have egg.
Got some
Worcestershire sauce, okay?
Yep, yep, yep.
Seafood seasoning.
Parsley.
Some cubed bread.
Very nice.
We have this beautiful
jumbo lump crabmeat.
Whoa! Whoa-oh!
Look at that!
Gonna mix this up.
Would you like me to flop
some mayo in there for you?
A little more.
Put that in there.
Okay.
In my world of crab cakes,
that's the ratio.
We put this in the refrigerator
for maybe a couple of hours.
Let it tighten up.
Now we're gonna do
the Gorgonzola sauce.
Okay.
First, we're gonna add
our clarified butter and flour
to make a roux.
Start out
a little milk.
Salt and pepper.
All right.
So, we're gonna simmer this
for 15 or 20 minutes.
Okay.
We're gonna make a reduction
here.
So we got wine.
We got some garlic
going in here.
Some shal-lots in here,
okay?
Shal-lots.
Yes. Got that?
Now we are gonna add it
right into our Béchamel sauce.
There we go.
We're gonna add
the Gorgonzola cheese.
Gonna simmer
for about five minutes,
just to get the cheese flavor
throughout everything.
We're gonna stuff our flounder
right now, young man.
Take this stuffing here,
okay?
Putting it
right in the center here.
And we're just rolling it up,
okay?
We're rolling
right along here.
Rolling right along.
Another one.
A little melted butter.
Yes.
We're gonna put some water
in here so it doesn't stick.
In the oven uncovered?
Yes.
How long?
Takes about 15 minutes.
Fish is out.
And how does it
get served?
On the top
of fried tomatoes.
Don't give small portions here,
do you, boss?
No. We use a lot of takeout
containers in this place.
Got the Gorgonzola sauce
on top.
Top with
a little green onions.
A little crumble
of Gorgonzola cheese.
There you go.
Well, you got to dig
the flounder.
You don't see enough flounder
anymore.
Mmm.
Just the richness in the crab
by itself
takes care of it.
The really nice
little gem on it
is getting
underneath there
and getting
that little fried-tomato piece.
The acid of that tomato
is nice.
You make the sauce,
you roast it off in the oven.
You didn't skimp here
one bit.
That is about as
old-school legit as they come.
Thank you, sir.
Nicely done, brother.
A flounder
Gorgonzola.
Flounder is delicious.
The portion size is incredible.
FIERI:
How's that flounder
and the fried Jersey tomatoes
treating you?
It's like a burst of seafood
in my mouth.
It's a burst of seafood
in your mouth.
FIERI: And even though
we're sitting on the coast,
this isn't just a seafood spot.
Cannelloni in the window.
Chef's also got some Italian
up his sleeve...
The best I've ever had.
There's Italian restaurants
that don't make it this good.
...when we come back.
FIERI: We're parked
at Somers Point, New Jersey,
at a landmark joint
with quite the colorful history.
The Anchorage has been here
for as long
as I can possibly remember.
MAN: This used to be a brothel
in the old days,
when they used to
run the liquor up the coast.
You really do
get a sense of history.
When we were a kid, this place
was a 7-for-1 beer joint.
So, 7 beers that had
7 ounces in each beer.
There you go.
For $1.
And that's
how you described it?
This was back in the '70s,
you know?
And it kind of got run-down.
FIERI: Then chef and owner
Don Mahoney came in
and turned things around
with dishes like this one.
I'm having their
homemade cannelloni dinner.
You can taste every single thing
in the dish.
All right,
so, what are we making, boss?
Making
the marinara sauce.
So, we're gonna start
with olive oil.
Chopped onions.
Garlic.
We're gonna cook this out.
Gotcha.
We're gonna add
our crushed tomatoes.
Gonna whip this up.
It's gonna simmer
for about 45 minutes.
Now time for the basil?
Yeah.
Salt.
Bay leaves.
Pepper.
Oregano.
So, let this go
for another 45.
Yeah.
So, what's the cannelloni?
Give me the rundown.
Olive oil.
Put some onions
in here.
Garlic.
I like the way
you handle the garlic, buddy.
You got ground veal.
Ground pork.
Ground chicken.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Cinnamon-amon-amon-amon-amon.
I always say it
like that, too.
Gonna mix this up,
okay?
With your hand.
Now we're gonna add
the ground beef.
Okay.
Oregano.
Basil.
One more time,
we're gonna do this.
How long are we gonna
let this cook down?
We're gonna cook this
for about 45 minutes.
Then we're gonna add
our spinach to there
and let it wilt
and work that in there.
Gotcha, boss.
Right now, we're gonna add
some lemon juice.
Eggs.
Parmesan cheese.
Mozzarella cheese.
Mix this up.
Add our ricotta cheese.
Beautiful.
Now what's up?
We're gonna stuff them
in these pasta shells.
Right there by hand.
So we get a little roll
on top of itself.
Sit it
on a sheet tray.
And then we're gonna
put some sauce on top.
And then
they go in the oven.
They'll be in the oven
about 35, 40 minutes.
Bring them out, they'll be nice,
bubbly, hot, and delicious.
Hit them
with a little sauce.
Mozzarella cheese
and more sauce.
And then back in for
another few minutes
to melt the cheese.
There you go.
Here we are.
We're gonna ladle
a little bit of marinara.
One.
Two to an order.
Sauce right on top.
I like
that tomato sauce.
Parmesan cheese
right here.
That's all she wrote.
Mmm.
I pick up
a little of that cinnamon.
Tender.
Super flavorful.
That pasta is absorbing
all of the juices.
It's awesome.
But you put so much time
and energy into this.
There's Italian restaurants
that don't make it this good.
This is awesome.
MAN:
Okay, cannelloni alla Bolognese.
It's very moist.
The sauce is very delicate.
MAN: The cheese and the meat
were just perfect.
Couldn't be better.
FIERI:
This is Chef Gibson.
He was the big winner
of "Rachael vs. Guy" season 2
of "Kids Cook-Off."
Tell me about this
from a chef's perspective.
It has
a lot of textural balance.
The sausage
has that crumbly feel.
The cheese
is ooey-gooey.
The cheese is what?
I'm sorry, Chef.
Ooey-gooey.
Inner child!
At least we can still remember
he's a kid.
MAN:
I'm very impressed.
The meal that we've had today
is absolutely fantastic.
I love it all.
I know the whole menu by heart.
You put a lot
into this.
I'm lucky
to be here.
Every day I walk in,
I know I'm lucky.
I don't
take it for granted.
You got good energy, buddy.
Nice job.
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
southwest to Gilbert, Arizona...
I try that, right?
...to a place putting out
pizza and pasta...
If I could come in
and get this,
I'd be here
two, three times a week.
...all in
one delicious dish.
[ Rapping ] ♪ Bak-ed ziti pizza,
bak-ed ziti pizza ♪
So, I'm here
in Gilbert, Arizona,
about 30 miles from Phoenix.
Now, I love coming down here.
I get to rip around
in the desert in my Razr,
there's great food,
really cool people.
I like the story of this place.
Let's see.
The dude is from Sicily, Italy.
He moves to New York,
meets his wife, has a family,
and then they all move here to
Gilbert to open a pizza joint.
That's right.
This is Sal's Gilbert Pizza.
Upside-down Sicilian ready.
It's a slice of New York
in the middle of the desert.
Grandma pizza.
WOMAN:
Flavors are outstanding.
You can smell it
when you walk in the door.
FIERI:
Thanks to Chef Sal Cuffaro,
who took over
this pizza/pasta joint in 2005.
So, is this New York-style?
Is this Italian-style?
New York-style
American pizza, yes.
Plus
a little of his own style...
Lasagna pizza ready.
FIERI: ...which means
piling the pies with pasta.
Baked ziti pizza.
I love baked ziti on the side.
I also love thin-crust pizza.
You put
the two of them together,
it makes a perfect pie.
What kind of pizza
do we make?
We got to make
bak-ed ziti pizza.
[ Rapping ] ♪ Bak-ed ziti pizza,
bak-ed ziti pizza ♪
Baked --
[ Beatboxing ]
Come on. Doesn't that
have a sound to it?
Got to do the dough first.
We start it with water.
Room-temperature water?
Yeah.
Then we put salt.
Sugar.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Of course.
Who taught you
how to make pizza?
I used to watch my mother
make pizza.
Then we put our yeast.
All of that together.
Now we got to
put the flour in.
High-gluten flour.
Got it.
We wait
about 10 minutes.
This is like skilled labor
for me.
We're gonna make a ziti?
Let's put the pasta
in the water first.
Okay.
Then we put
some marinara sauce.
Some cream.
Season it --
salt and pepper.
Let it cook
for about a few minutes.
Okay.
A little butter.
Grated Parmesan cheese.
Parsley.
Okay.
Pasta's ready to go in.
We'll let the pasta finish
cooking in the sauce, right?
Yeah,
about a couple minutes,
and then we're gonna parbake
the pizza dough.
We're gonna parbake
Otherwise --
'cause if we put that hot,
it would cook right through
the pizza dough.
All right.
Okay, we got to put
some whole-milk mozzarella.
A little bit
of cheese.
Gonna put the pasta now.
And I try that,
right?
Very nice.
A little more mozzarella.
A little grated Parmesan.
Put it back in the oven.
How long?
A couple minutes.
It's ready to go.
[ Whistles ]
There we go.
The dough
is nice and crispy.
Mmm.
I love pasta.
I love pizza.
But the key is,
the pasta's got to be al dente.
Yes.
And the dough
has to be crispy.
That right there --
That's the optimum bite.
If I could come in
and get this,
I'd be here
two, three times a week.
Mmm!
Nice job, man.
Thank you.
The sauce itself on the pizza
is delicious.
It's perfect
if I can't decide what I want --
pizza, pasta -- both.
The crust is crispy
but flaky at the same time.
Upside-down
Sicilian slice.
Sal being from Italy, the pizza
is absolutely phenomenal.
FIERI:
But not totally Italian.
You don't find pizza this big
in Italy.
No.
You go and make that in Italy,
people would be like --
They'd say, "You're crazy,"
or something.
MAN: Sal puts out
some very unusual pizzas.
They're brilliant.
Chicken Marsala pizza ready.
The chicken Marsala pizza is
one of my favorites of all time.
It's so flavorful
with the Marsala sauce on it.
Chicken Marsala.
Yes.
We just cleaned the chicken.
We're gonna season it.
Salt and pepper.
We'll dredge in flour.
Put some oil
into the pan,
so we're gonna brown the chicken
a couple minutes.
Okay.
Sauté the onions.
Put a little butter,
a little flour.
So, you make
a little roux out of this.
Yep.
Now we're gonna add
the Marsala wine.
Chicken stock.
Season it
with salt and pepper.
Add the mushrooms.
Now we got to
cut the chicken.
All this
goes on one pizza?
Yep.
[ Whistles ]
We're gonna let it
tighten up.
Let it cook down.
Now we got to parbake the crust
with a little mozzarella cheese.
Look at that.
Nice.
Huh?
The color.
Chicken Marsala on top.
Spread it out.
Mozzarella cheese.
Parmesan cheese.
Okay, back in the oven,
let it melt?
Yep. Three minutes.
Three minutes.
Okay, ready?
Yep.
Chicken Marsala pizza.
Oh!
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
It's creamy.
You get a little bit
of that Marsala.
The mushrooms are tender.
The chicken is super tender.
The pre-cooked pizza dough
just sucks that sauce in.
This is a pizza
that eats like a dinner.
The chicken itself
is very juicy.
Just having a fantastic meal
on top of a fantastic dough.
I love Sal's.
He's very imaginative.
That's the sign of a good chef.
CUFFARO:
Chicken scarpariello ready.
I know everybody in Italy
thinks you're crazy.
I think you're crazy, too.
I like crazy people.
Nice job, Sal.
Thank you.
Nice job.
FIERI:
Up next, a West Coast shout-out
to the South...
This is real-deal
barbecue, man.
...at a Bakersfield, California,
pit stop...
Bring the kids down.
Have a sandwich for four.
...loading up
a monster meaty mouthful.
If you order the sandwich,
does it come with a free beach
towel or anything like that?
So, when you're cruising down
Rosedale Highway going east,
right through northwest side
of Bakersfield, California,
just slow down and kind of
hang your head out the window.
[ Sniffs ]
What's that you smell?
Exactly -- killer barbecue.
We're talking mesquite charcoal
and some red oak,
cooking up
at a funky little place
called Salty's BBQ & Catering.
SALTERS:
Half-pound pulled-pork dinner!
I give this place a 10½.
It makes me feel
like I'm back in Oklahoma.
Pig sandwich
and green beans.
MAN:
The traffic's a little noisy,
but it doesn't
take away from the food.
FIERI: Which has been cooked up
curbside since 2012
by chef and owner Jeff Salters.
You can't have a name
that cool
and get in
the barbecue business.
Your last name
could be Sauce.
That's the only name
that would be any better
than having Salters
as your last name.
WOMAN: It's really kind of
entertaining to watch
knowing that
that's your chicken right there
or that's your tri-tip.
It's great.
Salty's Special.
Having the Salty's Special.
You got the best combination --
You got tri-tip, pulled pork,
and you got the barbecue sauce
on top of it.
What are we making?
We're gonna make
our Salty's rub.
We got lemon pepper.
Some garlic powder.
And then
we're gonna put in allspice.
A little
seasoned salt?
seasoned salt.
And then we just throw in
a little basil.
Looks like an Indian
spice market right there.
All right, so what
are we gonna put this on?
We're gonna put this
on our tri-tip.
We like to make sure
it's covered.
We'll leave it on
overnight.
So, you're setting these up
for the next day.
We are.
Now we're gonna rub our
pork butts with our Salty's rub.
We're gonna put them
in our smoker for 12 hours.
Then we're gonna
lay the tri-tip out.
Got it.
We put it on by hand.
Because by foot
would be awkward?
Very.
So, this will go on
for about --
About 45 minutes.
Giddyup.
Barbecue sauce.
What type of barbecue sauce
are you into?
Kind of
a sweet, smoky, tangy.
Oh.
We're gonna start
with a little ketchup here.
Brown sugar.
Hickory smoke.
Soy sauce.
Worcestershire?
Worcestershire.
Apple cider vinegar.
A little bit of H2O.
A little bit
of vegetable oil.
Our yellow mustard in.
Then we put a little bit
of black pepper in there.
And is this the standard sauce
for all the barbecue?
Yes, it is.
Gonna make this sandwich
or not?
We're gonna get there.
You're killing me,
boss.
And when you have it,
it's gonna change your life.
It's gonna change my waistband,
is what it's gonna change.
All right, so, now we're gonna
pull our pork butts out.
Okay.
Just check this.
Look at the bark
on that bad boy.
Nice smoke ring.
Ohh.
That doesn't suck.
Here we go.
[ Whistles ]
We gonna break it down,
get it nice and chopped up.
So, now this is --
That's ready?
Grab the tri-tip
and we're gonna slice it.
Time to build it.
Rock 'n' roll.
So, we're gonna start off
with laying some tri-tip out.
Put a little bit
of our pulled pork in there.
Put our barbecue sauce
on there.
Add some yellow peppers.
Top it off with
a little bit of our coleslaw.
If you order the sandwich,
does it come with
a free beach towel
or anything like that?
Barbecue sauce
is spot-on.
Excellent tang.
Not too much smoke.
Pulled pork's great.
Really get that deep, rich,
great flavor from the smoke.
It's a really good sauce.
Bring the kids down.
Have a sandwich for four.
[ Chuckles ]
This is real-deal
barbecue, man.
Nicely done.
Barbecue sauce
just plays off the meat.
They nailed it
with that sandwich.
You want to find
really good barbecue,
you know
what you got to do?
You got to find out
where super-athletes eat.
Number 6, Cody Kessler
from USC Trojans.
You're from Bakersfield.
When you come back, this is
one of your go-to joints?
Yeah.
You know, living in L.A.,
there's a lot
of great places to eat,
but nothing
kind of this original.
SALTERS: Pork rib dinner,
green beans, chili beans.
Jeff knows what he's doing.
I've been cooking for friends
and family probably 20 years.
Barbecue the whole time?
Barbecue, yeah.
Our tag is
we're the best of both worlds --
smoking and grilling.
That's smoking.
FIERI:
And this is grilling.
Half-chicken dinner,
chili beans, potato salad.
It's so tender, so moist.
You just pick it
right off the bone.
We're gonna make chicken.
Grilled chicken.
Let's do it.
We take a whole chicken.
We split them.
Put a couple slits in there
so the wings will lay flat
when we're grilling it.
Now we're gonna make
our marinade.
We got orange juice.
A little bit
of lemon juice.
Then we put the chickens
in the marinade.
Nice and covered.
So, now we're gonna hit it
with the dry rub?
We're not gonna be shy
about putting it on.
Then we're gonna cover it with
foil. Let it marinade overnight.
Then we'll go
to the grill.
Absolutely.
Got it.
So, we've been grilling
this chicken about 45 minutes.
We're ready
to pull it off.
Hit it.
[ Whistles ]
Good-looking bird.
We just tear them by hand.
We serve them in quarters.
This is
your half-chicken dinner.
That's great bird,
man.
Tender.
Good smoke flavor.
I like that
it just falls off the bone.
Got a little texture
in the skin.
You killed it, man.
Nice job.
WOMAN:
I like the crisp outside pieces,
so it's got that nice, like,
char on the outside.
The chicken is very tender.
Falls off the bone.
It's smoky flavor.
Just taste a little bit
of mesquite in there.
What makes this special
is Jeff Salters.
Cool thing about this
is you're not trying to do
10,000 things.
You're able to take it,
harness it,
do it right, and win.
Impressive.
Thank you very much.
You want to become friends
with this cat.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
You know what time it is,
everybody at home.
Get up on the couch
and make some noise!
It's time for...
bak-ed ziti pizza!
Yi-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi!