Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
...We're going
cross-country...
Crazy.
...for a tasty,
multi-continent tour.
You know,
it is swimsuit season.
In Atlanta, Georgia...
This is when the funky
of the folk come out.
...a place grilling up
some mega meat.
Look at that!
...stacked into
serious sandwiches.
That's
ridiculously big.
In Denver, Colorado...
The bomb.
...a colorful
South American joint...
A lot going on.
...scratch-making
a taste of Brazil.
This has got
so much flavor.
Then over in downtown...
I just want more of it.
...a unique
quick service spot...
Brother, I am telling you --
This is better than good.
...dishing out Indian curry
packed with a punch.
You see the sweat
coming on?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Inman Park
in Atlanta, Georgia,
right between the Highlands
and Little 5 Points.
Now, to you and me,
that doesn't really mean much,
but to the locals,
this is a famous neighborhood
that's just blowing up
with some righteous restaurants
like this joint.
Welcome to Folk Art.
♪♪
Folks southern fry
in the window.
This place is the definition
of southern hospitality.
Fried green tomatoes
for table six.
The menus great
from top to bottom.
FIERI: And cooked up by
Atlanta native Jason Hill...
Lobster roll in the window.
Let's pick it up.
...Who with
co-owner Randy Parks
turned a hundred-year-old
former grocery store
into this funky, folksy joint
in 2013.
What's the food?
Keep it simple, but we
dress it up, make it artful.
Sort of like
a funky, upscale.
Funky upscale.
Meatball burger.
Let's pick it up.
Great meatball flavor.
You can barely get your mouth
around it, but it's really good.
All right,
what are we into?
A marinara
for our meatball burger.
[ Southern accent ]
Marinar'?
Marinar'.
Gonna make
some marinar'.
We're gonna dump in
our diced onions.
Diced red bell peppers.
Then our chopped garlic.
[ Whistles ]
We use a healthy bit
of garlic.
Okay.
Our red chili flakes.
Then we sweated down
our onions.
We're gonna
put our paprika in.
Salt.
Little bit of sugar.
This is my thyme.
Okay.
Margarine, parsley.
Fresh
concasse tomatoes.
Conca-say what?
[ Laughter ]
Just a little bit
of water.
How long
is this gonna cook?
About 10 minutes.
So you hit
the immersion blender into it,
then drop the basil in,
and then hit it just a little
bit to break the basil up.
Yep.
Now we're into
the meatball burger.
Meatball burger.
Okay.
So, we make croutons,
and then we grind it up.
Oh, that's
a good-tasting crouton.
And then diced onions.
You're not gonna brown those off
or anything?
Nope. Nope, raw.
Fresh garlic.
That's going in
raw, too?
Raw.
A little bit of cumin.
Little bit of black pepper,
fresh thyme, oregano,
and this is kind of the secret,
I think -- the chili powder.
And a little bit of salt.
Now we're gonna add
some fresh eggs.
Beautiful. Flat top?
Flat top.
Is it one patty?
This one's three.
Three patties?.
You know,
it is swimsuit season.
That's right.
We put on the provolone cheese,
caramelized onions,
the wonderful mushrooms.
House-made
marinara sauce.
And then
our house-made pickles.
Toss our hand-cut fries.
There you go.
Holy moly.
Look at that.
Love the sautéed mushrooms.
Nice little kiss
of the marinara.
That right there is screaming
Italian family Sunday dinner.
That's ridiculously big.
You got problems,
just like that guy at Pinky's
in Charlotte,
North Carolina.
Greg, that's your twin.
Close.
The meatball burger.
The sandwiches are
like complete meals.
WOMAN: It's got
some southern kick to it,
and it makes it
totally awesome.
Bacon cheeseburger.
Is this a typical type
of Atlanta restaurant?
I'd say it's fun
because it's very much
a part of the neighborhood.
WOMAN: It brings
a lot of people together,
a lot of neighbors
that we know.
The natural light
makes it really warm
and the old signs just make you
feel kind of nostalgic.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
The pulled-pork sandwich.
Bad to the bone in the window,
table 24.
It's not your typical
pulled-pork sandwich.
It really is just something
uniquely different.
What are we onto now,
brother?
All right,
we've got our pork butt.
We do a simple brine
of brown sugar and kosher salt.
One of my favorite
Rolling Stones songs.
There you go.
"Kosher Salt."
A little bit
of lukewarm water,
just enough to dissolve
the sugar and salt.
And then
so you don't poach it,
you're gonna hit it
with a little bit of ice.
That's it.
And it's a fast brine.
We let this sit
overnight.
Okay, so we have brined
the butt.
And then we're gonna rub
our dry rub on it.
Massage it in.
How long are we gonna go?
12 hours.
12 hours at 250.
Yep.
Now what are we making?
All right, we're making
our date barbecue sauce.
Date?
I had some dates one day,
and I was like,
You know, I'm gonna thicken
a barbecue sauce with it,
make it
a little bit different."
I'm telling you
it's good.
This is when the funky
of the folk come out.
Dried dates.
Dry guajillo peppers
with a little bit of the heat.
Big old chuck of garlic.
Chili powder.
Brown sugar, cumin.
Rice wine vinegar.
Little bit of water.
Cook it for about 10 minutes,
till it comes up to a nice boil.
Throw it in our blender
and blend it up.
Okay.
Take our big old slices
of white bread.
Take our pork straight off
in nice, big chunks.
Piece of Gruyere cheese.
Few caramelized onions.
And this is
our date barbecue sauce,
which you're
very interested in.
Date barbecue sauce.
Little bit of our collard-green
coleslaw goes on there.
And we top it.
Another petit diet sandwich.
Just like the meatball burger
had its own unique identity,
the same thing
with this sandwich.
You get the tang coming out
of the raw onion and the slaw.
The pork's got its own,
you know, barbecuey flavor,
a little bit of that smoky
coming through,
and a little bit of sweet,
but not as much sweet
as I anticipated...
...with the date.
It's got
so much going on.
It's a great sandwich, man.
Sweet, thank you.
MAN:
And the bad to the bone.
Nice, tangy sauce.
There's some heat in it.
It's creamy, it's rich.
It's really something different.
Pork verde -- table two.
Let's pick it up.
The food's perfect
when you come here.
Just a great place
all the way around.
Fantastic and unique.
Thank you.
Well done, brother.
Thanks, Guy.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Denver, Colorado...
That is outrageous.
...a place cooking up
killer curry...
This is
tikka masala gone wild.
...served
with a side of heat.
A little fire
in the belly.
♪♪
So, I'm here in the Rhino
district of Denver, Colorado,
just a few blocks away
from where the Rockies play.
Now, I have everybody
and their mother
sending me recommendations
for "Triple D,"
but when my buddy Frank Matson,
who happens to be
the owner of Citizen Pictures,
the executive producer of
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives,"
ay, "Hey, Guy, I got a place
you've got to check out,"
well, enough said.
This is
Biju's Little Curry Shop.
Coconut curry chicken
it is.
The freshest Indian food
I've ever had.
Beef with biriyani,
that sounds excellent.
It's a completely different
cuisine that you're used to
when you think
of India food.
FIERI:
This is Frank Matson.
Frank and I have been buddies
for a long time,
and he said this is a joint
you got to see.
What makes it so special?
Biju is just making
really great-tasting food
that's healthy
for you, too.
The kind of food the owner
Biju Thomas specializes in,
as a personal chef
for pro athletes,
and now he's bringing it
to the masses.
Is this fast food?
Is this...
Fast casual. So, people
come through the line here.
We walk them
through every step.
Everything's in a bowl.
Everything's either rice
or as a salad.
You've got chicken, beef,
or vegetarian combo.
That's pretty much
everything.
That's it.
They have so many options here.
The spicy beef over rice.
I usually get the biriyani rice
with the vindaloo chicken.
The chicken vindaloo
over the yucca.
If you look at
south Indian food,
every dish starts
exactly the same --
with a fresh curry base,
mustard seeds, ginger,
garlic, chilies.
Really?
Fresh curry leaves.
This goes into everything.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Fresh curry leaves?
I don't know that I've ever
smelled curry leaves.
Yeah, this is the --
It's like pandas eat this.
Basically --
[ Laughter ]
I mean, it's bitter
on the palate,
but it's got
an awesome smell.
Yeah.
We're gonna
chop all this up.
We got some red onions.
Little bit of garlic.
Some ginger.
Serranos and jalapeños.
Wow, there's a little Latin spin
coming out there.
Grab some fresh curry leaves
and fresh cilantro.
We can start basically any
of our sauces we want.
This is the foundation?
Yes, sir.
And then from that,
we can take that
into any different direction
with the beef or the chicken --
anything at all we
want to go to.
Okay, next up?
This is our basic dry spice mix
for vindaloo.
Vindaloo is
a spicy curry.
Toasted coriander.
Coriander is the base
for a lot of the curries.
It's kind of neutral,
it's not too peppery.
A little bit of lemon.
Then we have
some toasted fennel.
Black peppercorns.
Big peppercorns.
Curry leaves.
The dry version.
Cumin seeds.
Mmm.
These are not toasted.
Black mustard seeds.
Sweet paprika.
So, we go with
a ton of that in there.
Turmeric.
Also for color.
Turmeric is one of the heavy
colors in Indian food, correct?
Yeah. We finish with some
extra-hot Indian ground pepper.
All of that?
Yeah, we want it
to be hot.
All right,
so now we grind it.
That's it. Now we're gonna
cook the chicken.
I always work with
chicken thigh.
It has a little bit
more substance.
The chicken thigh
is done.
A little oil in the pan.
Right.
Some chicken.
We got a little salt
and pepper.
While that's happening, I'm
gonna start our vindaloo sauce.
A little oil.
Let me taste this,
by the way.
Is it gonna be hot?
Gonna be a little peppery.
Not too crazy.
Good, right?
Mmm. It's awesome.
Spice mix.
That's for one dish?
That's the one dish.
You know, when you get
curry mix powder at home,
people use
like a teaspoon.
Nobody uses a teaspoon.
That doesn't do anything.
Our chopped curry base.
Smells good, though, right?
It smells fantastic.
Okay, tamarind paste.
Okay.
Nice sweetness,
a little of that tang.
Give it another stir.
Some fresh lemon juice.
Wow.
That's
fresh-squeezed lemon.
Regular distilled
white vinegar.
This is crazy.
Give it
a nice sprinkle of salt.
Gorgeous -- look at that.
You've done this before.
And a little agua?
A little water
to give it a little sauce.
That good?
Beautiful, yeah.
And you let that
tighten up.
Is this now
where we should be?
Yeah.
Oh.
Okay, so the chicken gets
nice and tender.
Yeah, so this gets combined,
then we have the curry.
I'm gonna plate it up.
So, normally,
we'd come off the line,
so I'll just do it.
I'm gonna start
with some chicken vindaloo.
That's how much
you get?
Yeah, you get
chicken vindaloo.
You add some yucca.
Yucca put
too much on.
THOMAS: I'm gonna put
a little bit of slaw in here.
And then I'm gonna put
some of our Ardicheri
because you wanted it to be
extra hot.
I didn't say that
at all.
That little nugget of death
right there.
Are you kidding me,
dude?
Oh, that's good.
Fantastic flavor, right?
Nice tang, nice acid.
There's tons of
different textures going on.
This is
tikka masala gone wild.
A little bit of spice.
I will admit I got a little bit
of a sweat brow going.
You see the sweat
coming on?
I mean,
I just want more of it.
Brother, I am tell you
this is better than good.
I can understand why
my boy Frank sent me here.
Chicken vindaloo
and yucca.
Fantastic.
Just big chunks of chicken.
There's all kinds of vegetables
so it's crunchy.
Not too saucy.
It's fresh, it's tasty.
MAN: It's definitely got
some spice to it
that I wasn't quite
ready for.
I'm tearing up a little bit.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
And if heat's not your thing...
Sometimes I come in, I don't
feel like that much spice,
I can tone it down.
You can always
kick it up a notch
with two or three different
types of spices.
What are we
gonna make next?
THOMAS:
Beautiful, bright curried beef.
I'm hanging out here
in Denver, Colorado,
with a crazy guy
named Biju.
When we come back,
it's another outstanding dish.
Biriyani with beef --
It's really unique.
It's something that you wouldn't
necessarily think of
when you think of curry.
You sell sweatpants?
[ Laughter ]
See you in a minute.
All right,
here we are back in Denver.
I've finished
my bowl of vindaloo.
I had a small nap, and now we're
into another fantastic dish.
FIERI: something Biju Thomas
has a knack for --
Indian food
for active folks
like the athletes
he used to cook for.
In the last 10 years,
I've focused mostly
in the cycling and sports world.
Including one who just happens
to be a buddy of mine
from my home town of Santa Rosa,
pro cyclist Levi Leipheimer.
You know this cat
right here?
Yeah, Levi.
I need you to sign off on
this guy. Is he the real deal?
He sort of straddles that line
between gourmet cooking
and fuel for getting out there
and doing your best performance,
but it tastes great.
Can't get any better sign-off
than that.
This food is so different
from other Indian food.
It's layers of flavor.
It's real ingredients.
It's complex,
and I think that's the genius
that Biju's brought here.
What's your favorite dish?
I think the curried beef.
It's a cinnamon garlic
brazed beef.
Awesome curried beef.
That's what this is.
I'm gonna put
a little oil in the pan.
This is chuck.
Norris?
As in Norris.
A bit of salt and pepper.
So you're just gonna
sear that off. Next step?
Just like with the vindaloo,
we have our beef curry mix.
And that goes in.
I just cannot believe the amount
of spice that goes into it.
That's what makes
the difference.
The spicier we make it,
the more people love it.
This is our curry base.
And this, too, you know,
you're not shy about
how much you put in there.
That,
roast them together.
I'm gonna add
a little bit of water
and let this simmer
for about 90 minutes.
At the very end, we have
a little bit of ground cinnamon,
some ground anise,
coriander.
Okay.
Now we're gonna make
the Samandhi.
Samandhi is our roasted coconut
and dry red chili chutney.
Chili?
Yep.
These guys will be
nice and hot.
I always like
when my chilies
outweigh all the other
ingredients nine to one.
Exactly.
Okay.
What is this called?
"Guy Fieri, This Was Your Life"?
[ Laughs ]
I'm gonna start with
a little bit of coconut oil
and mustard seeds.
Fresh curry leaves --
your favorite.
A little bit of minced garlic,
ginger, a little tamarind.
Smells awesome so far.
Onions.
Okay.
Fresh coconut --
comes from India.
So then we add
our chilies.
This is the most chilies
I've ever seen
go into one sauce this size.
Go for it. Do it all.
There you go.
So, we roast that off,
toast it till the peppers
start to burn a little bit.
There it is.
Crazy.
And we're ready
for the blender.
Adding a little bit of water
and salt.
That's our Samandhi base.
Wow, that looks hot.
So we start with our biriyani,
which is a fruit nut rice.
Lentils, beef.
We got a little bit of slaw.
Got some Thai chilies.
The radishes and jalapeños.
A little bit
of lemon juice.
And salt.
So, that's our slaw.
Indians don't do that.
So, this is not an Indian side,
doing the slaw?
That's totally something
I borrowed.
This is the ground-coconut
Samandhi that we just made.
I'll have a bowl of Samandhi,
please.
Dude, it would be great
on anything.
That is outrageous.
Not too much heat
by any means.
It just has
so much going on.
Then you get a touch
of the sweetness of the coconut,
and then you get
the richness of the beef.
A little acidity
of that slaw.
Put a little fire
in the belly.
Wake you up a little bit.
Biriyani with beef.
It's really intense flavors.
WOMAN:
There's huge chunks of beef.
My favorite part, actually,
is the slaw.
It just adds a lot of good,
fresh flavor in there.
MAN: It's been
a great experience so far,
I think it's so awesome here.
This is the place to go
in Denver.
When my buddy, Frank,
told me about this place,
I said,
"You know, I'll check it out."
You didn't
let me down, man.
Nice.
Real deal.
Thanks, buddy.
You got to come see this guy --
no question.
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
just outside of downtown...
I like that.
...to a funky
Brazilian bistro.
What a dish.
...that's blowing up
the flavor combos.
Let me look around.
There might be something
you didn't put in there.
♪♪
So, I'm here on the north side
of Denver, Colorado,
just a few minutes
from downtown,
and I'm right around the corner
from Tocabe.
You remember that place, right?
They made the fantastic salsa
with the hominy?
Well, anyhow, believe it or not,
right down the street,
a funky little joint,
this is Cafe Brazil.
The food is 100% intense.
[ Zarlinga speaking Portuguese ]
Everything is really fresh.
The ingredients taste like they
just came out of the garden.
FIERI: And just like
they came out of Brazil.
Colombiana, pick up.
'Cause that's the type
of contemporary South American
cuisine owner Tony Zarlinga
has been cooking up since
he opened this joint in 1992.
You come in here,
it's like going on vacation.
You can be outside in the snow,
and you walk in,
and you're transported
into Brazil.
One bolinhos.
The bolinhos are so good.
MAN: There's pork and cheese,
a bit of spice,
and then a little bit
of crispy on the outside.
If I go to Brazil, this is gonna
be a dish I'm gonna find.
Yeah, the bolinho.
The bolinho.
I've got
sweet potato working.
I start the mash.
Okay.
Shrimp in.
Salumi.
This is a mix of lomo and
salchichon, two Spanish salumis.
Mozzarella.
Feta cheese.
Don't forget-a the feta.
Smoked cheddar.
Mmm.
Smoked cheddar, wow.
Chile paquin.
A lot of
red chili flakes.
Yes, sir.
Sea salt,
sriracha, eggs.
Panko.
What a dish.
Mint, oregano, and basil.
Shall we?
You gonna tickle
that the whole time there?
It's therapeutic.
Voilà.
Now we will flour
our bolinho.
We'll fry that up,
350 degrees.
Yeah.
Béchamel sauce.
This is Italian parsley.
Pickled pepper.
Yeah.
And finish
with fresh mint leaf.
There we go.
This has got
so much flavor.
I get a little kick of feta,
a little bit of the shrimp,
I get a little bit
of the salumi.
The mozzarella cheese
is probably one of
my favorite parts.
It's creamy,
it's a little tender.
Sauce goes along great
with it.
If you're gonna eat something
fried, eat something like that.
Very nice, Chef.
Excellent job.
It's really crispy on
the outside, but on the inside,
it's creamy, and it just melts
in your mouth.
How would you describe
Brazilian food?
A marriage
of different ethnic groups --
Portuguese, Spanish, Asian,
Middle Eastern.
You get flavors
that you find in South America.
Everything
that comes to you here
is always set up beautifully.
Getting ready
for Julianna.
Julianna was amazing.
WOMAN: It's the perfect dish
because it's got the rice,
the prawns, succulent
pulled pork, some greens.
Was that
succulent pulled pork?
So delicious.
FIERI:
What are we making this time?
La Julianna.
Berkshire pork, soy.
Worcestershire.
And then every single thing
that we own in the kitchen
is going to go in.
Almost.
Aleppo pepper.
Cumin. Cinnamon.
Fresh garlic.
Lemon peel.
With paprika.
Sea salt, black pepper.
Onion powder.
Chile paquin.
Chipotle paprika.
Raw sugar.
Apricot marmalade.
Of course.
Sriracha,
cherub tomato, onion.
Mango and
Valencia orange juice.
Let me look around.
There might be something
you didn't put in there.
Almost the kitchen sink.
I was just gonna say.
Do you want me to go get it?
[ Laughs ]
Let it rub,
and it goes to the fridge.
How long is it gonna
go in the fridge.
Three days.
It sits like that
for three days?
Three days.
Then we're gonna cook it?
Yes. 500 degrees
for 6 hours.
We've got
our pork coming out.
We start to pull.
I like that.
Gonna go...
Into the sauce.
...Into the orange sauce.
Next?
We're gonna get
the shrimp working.
Salt and a little chili.
Collards.
Greens on a flat top.
Can't say I've ever seen it.
Garlic powder.
Chili, Black pepper,
a little salt.
And now a little...
Water.
Dome.
Dome you forget it.
Gonna flip the shrimp.
A lot going on.
Rice, farofa,
which is toasted yucca flour.
A little bit
of butter and shallots
gives it
a nice crunchy texture.
Collards.
A bit of cheese.
Campagna.
Pulled pork.
It's called
a lumberjack plate here.
Italian parsley.
Gulf shrimp.
Plantains.
I don't know
where to start.
The pork is
incredibly tender.
What is this called again,
the dust?
Farofa.
The bomb.
That apricot marmalade
really carries a punch.
Shrimp is an extra kiss.
Plantains are nice and sweet.
When you put the whole package
together, nice job, Chef.
You got every flavor
you can think of in one dish.
I like this place a lot.
Now that we found it,
we're here all the time.
Oh, that was good.
Thank you.
Nice job.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
What's your favorite show?
"Triple D" -- duh.
Duh.
[ Laughter ]
What else do you watch?
Nothing.
Just "Triple D," all the time.
[ Laughter ]