I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
Get your carnivore on...
This is screaming
the hunch.
...'cause it's time
to beef things up around here.
Should serve this
in a kiddie pool.
In Plymouth, Massachusetts...
Hey, oh, now.
Here, now.
...a funky joint
stuffing steak into pretzels...
[ Both mumble ]
...and putting a swap
into shepherd's pie.
Chug that down.
In Minneapolis, Minnesota...
That says swimsuit.
...a favorite
neighborhood hangout...
That will make you want to sell
your home and move in.
...stacking up major
mouthwatering meat.
Brother, you can't go
any more right.
That is fantastic.
Plus, a real-deal deli
in Atlanta, Georgia...
Good, old-school,
New York style.
...where I'm plowing
into the pastrami...
That's happy hash
right there, dude.
[ Laughs ]
...and bringing along
some backup.
Aah!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
When I come to Atlanta,
you know I got to hook up
with my buddy Chef G. Garvin.
'Cause it's this cat's hometown,
and he knows the killer
food scene around here.
Man, that baby's got
some horsepower!
I can't believe you drove it
that way, dude.
Dude, I told you,
if you come to Atlanta,
I'd bring you to the real-deal
deli right here.
In all these new buildings,
real-deal deli?
My man.
This is The General Muir.
Reubens at table 4 are up.
-This is a great Jewish deli.
-Matzo ball soup.
-Everything's made from scratch.
-Got the pastrami sandwich.
It feels like New York,
with the tile to the ceiling...
Atwood chairs, patina and brass,
the whole bit, yeah.
-It's got the groove.
-Yep.
FIERI:
And that groove comes from
New Jersey transplant
Todd Ginsberg,
who got some advice
about opening this joint
with his partners in 2012.
My grandparents owned a deli,
and my dad said,
"You should think
about opening a deli.
You're having a kid."
-That was it.
-That's it.
So, why The General Muir?
My partner,
Jennifer Johnson,
her grandparents
were Holocaust survivors
and came over
on a U.S. refugee ship
called the General Muir.
-Unbelievable story.
-Isn't that great?
That's unbelievable.
FIERI:
Chef Todd honors that every day
by keeping this place real-deal.
They do some creative stuff,
but they're still nailing
the things that are really
touchstones about Jewish delis.
Number-one thing on the menu?
Love the hash.
Smoked hash
to the window.
So tasty. It's so tender.
It's amazing.
-Chef, what are we into?
-Pastrami.
Oh!
I am body by pastrami.
-Love pastrami.
-How we doing it, Chef?
All right,
we're making the brine.
Water, salt, sugar.
Definitely pink salt.
Garlic, cloves, peppercorns,
coriander seed.
Crushed red chili flakes,
bay leaf.
What is this thing,
the Injector 9000?
It is.
Have you had
your flu shot?
-Yes, sir.
-Lucky.
-Thank you for your concern.
-Well, I'm here.
We're gonna put that
in there like that.
Take half
of the brisket here.
Let me see you work
your wicked needle.
Go like this.
There we go.
Now we're gonna pour
the rest over it,
and it's gonna go 10 days.
Yeah.
After the 10 days,
we bring it out,
and then we're gonna hit it
with a dry rub?
Yep, and coriander
and peppercorns.
And go to the smoker.
Smokes for about eight hours.
Close, we can go.
No one's slow to the door.
And then we steam it
for about six hours.
That looks good to me.
Mmm!
All right,
now we're gonna make the hash?
Throw some schmaltz.
Just straight-up
chicken fat.
Potatoes.
Now we're adding
our diced pastrami.
Salting the potatoes.
A little fresh pepper.
Nice golden-brown.
Peppers. Caramelized onions.
Little cabbage.
Now we're gonna mix it up.
That's happy hash
right there, dude.
Couple eggs on there.
Some parsley.
All right.
Our smoked hash.
Mmm!
Dude, the pastrami --
It's the extra bark
on the outside, that smoke.
The added piece of the cabbage,
just totally key.
Caramelized onions
are really nice.
Love the red bell pepper.
You need that color in there.
Nice and tender.
It's unbelievable.
What you guys are doing
is absolutely setting the trend
for a whole new
style of deli.
Smoked hash.
I've never had anything like
that before, even in New York.
It's incredible.
It's the perfect mix of
a breakfast/brunch experience.
Can't find this
anywhere else in Atlanta.
So, we're hanging out here
in Atlanta, Georgia,
at The General Muir.
When we come back, we're gonna
make bagels and lox knockout.
Yes.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" here
in Atlanta, Georgia,
hanging out with
Mr. Atlanta, Georgia, G. Garvin.
We're at The General Muir,
and I got to tell you something.
We just had good, old-school,
New York-style pastrami.
And that's just the beginning
of Chef Todd Ginsberg's
legit Jewish-deli lineup.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
-This.
-The Maven.
Maven up.
Maven in Yiddish
does mean "expert."
It is an expertly made platter.
And it just is so good.
-What are we making first?
-Bagels.
Favorite bagel?
All bagel.
[ Record scratches ]
I just love their face.
They both went,
"The what?"
But you know what I mean --
all, everything.
No, no, no!
Okay, let's get into it.
Water. Salt.
-What's this?
-Oil and corn malt.
And it also goes into the water
that you boil bagels in.
Is that what creates
the glisten, the sheen?
Exactly right.
High-gluten flour,
dried yeast,
and then we'll go ahead and turn
this on for seven minutes.
Got it.
Next, we're cut into it.
About 5 ounces.
Flatten them out
a little bit.
And then three rollovers
back towards you.
Roll it out
about that long.
Just fold it over.
Okay, so it's kind of like
bread knuckles.
Put these onto this tray right
here that's been lightly oiled.
Let it proof overnight.
That slow fermentation
kind of develops that nice --
That yeasty flavor.
Now they go swimming?
Yep.
See them kind of puffing up
a little bit?
Take our handy spider.
And then we're gonna spray them
with some water.
Sprinkle the first side.
Everything spice, all right?
You get both sides.
Oh, yeah.
Now, how long do these
go in the oven for?
About 15 minutes?
-At what temp?
-450 high.
So, what are we doing?
Making our smoked trout salad
for the Maven.
So, the Maven gets smoked trout
salad, lox, black cod...
And Nova.
-Like Aldo Nova?
-That's the one.
-"Fantasy"?
-"Xanadu."
Aldo Nova
did not do "Xanadu."
Olivia Newton-John did "Xanadu"
in roller skates.
You two loved the movie.
I'm out.
You know any of the words
to "Xanadu"?
-You do not.
-What's your wager?
My wager is...
raw egg.
Raw egg, baby.
I don't know, man.
Then you lost!
No, no,
I didn't really bet.
-Oh, no, no, no!
-I was gonna shake.
Give me that raw egg up.
Oh, man.
You gonna cry about it?
Let's go, let's go.
No, no, no!
Oh!
I was going to town.
[ Laughter ]
Give me two eggs.
Aah!
They went down.
Where you at?
-Smoked trout salad.
-Okay.
We're gonna take some mayo,
sour cream.
-Whisk it.
-Okay.
-Cucumber.
Italian parsley.
Pinch of salt.
And lots of fresh
cracked pepper -- lots.
♪♪
Just gonna
fold this over.
-And that's all she wrote.
-That's it.
Now we're starting to build
our Maven platter.
Garnishes or accoutrements --
scallion-caper cream cheese.
It's our house-cured lox.
Got a few nice pieces
of Nova here.
Trout salad.
Got a couple pieces of sable,
which is a black cod.
We cure it in-house.
And our all bagels.
-All bagels.
-All day.
Take that.
Dig in.
Ah!
Great crust.
New York deli all day long.
Individually, everything has
its own taste and identity.
And then,
when you marry it all together,
it's like elevated taste.
Thank you.
Smoked salmon and the Nova
are very delicious --
nice and tender.
It goes well with the bagels
and the cream cheese.
WOMAN: The sable here
is done really, really well.
It's a fish that,
if you've not tried it before,
I highly recommend, and you will
definitely become a fan.
The trout salad is a takeoff
on the whitefish
that we'd normally get
in New York. I love that.
Think everybody's gonna be
really happy coming here.
You guys have not only brought
an original taste,
but you brought
the original attitude
about how you do it.
Outstanding, Chef.
Killin' it.
Putting Georgia on the map.
We're loading
my trunk right now
with corned-beef pastrami
and bagels,
also some of the smoked fish.
And, yes, G.,
you can drive home.
Vroom, vroom, baby!
Coming up, we're mixing it up
in Plymouth, Massachusetts...
Worcestershire sauce!
"What's this here?" sauce.
...with a new piece
to a meaty pie...
Oh, yeah.
...alongside
a tasty pretzel twist.
Point on, man.
♪♪
So, I'm in area
that a lot of people call
"America's hometown."
That's right --
Plymouth, Massachusetts.
Now, when you come
to a tourist area like this?
Where do you want to eat?
Right on. Where the locals eat.
And from what people
are telling me,
this is the joint --
the Driftwood Publick House
& Oysteria.
I got your tater for table 1.
It's definitely a great, great
spot to come and eat.
It's funky. It's just not
your average place.
Tory, oyster chowder -- boom.
-The food's unique.
-As unique as the man.
Yes.
That would be owner
Matt Hennessy,
who returned to his roots when
he opened this joint in 2012.
MAN: Matt's a great guy.
He's a local kid,
sowed his oats
out in the big cities
of Chicago and Boston,
and now he's come back home.
FIERI:
That's quite a beard.
You need it
for the winter.
Matt's getting it done up here.
Classic home cooking,
but way better than at home.
Here's that Philly pretzel.
MAN: The best cheesesteak
that you've ever had
wrapped in pretzel dough.
People definitely come here
just for this pretzel.
All right, so,
let's get into this.
So, we're starting off
with a little bit of oil.
Take our beef shoulders,
hit it with a little bit
of salt and pepper.
Sear it on both sides.
Okay.
Take them off
and put them to the side.
Add some fresh white onion,
garlic, our house herb mixture.
Let this sweat down
for a little bit.
Okay.
I'm gonna add some
Worcestershire sauce.
Some what?
Worcestershire sauce!
"What's this here?" sauce.
Our locally brewed
golden ale.
All right, so,
now this goes in here?
Yes.
What temp
are we gonna cook this at?
250 for about 5 hours.
And that's gonna get stuffed
inside the pretzel.
Yes.
We got our dough done.
We're gonna low this out to,
like, a long rectangular shape.
Gonna take
our shredded beef shoulder,
shredded American cheese.
Nice processed
American cheese.
A little bit of egg wash
on the sides.
Just gonna fold that over.
So it is a pretzel
and a calzone have a baby.
Oh, yeah.
You get a lot of egg wash
on there.
That's what gives it
that nice like --
Nice sheen.
Top it off
with some pretzel salt.
Bake this in the oven
at what temp?
475, 10 to 12 minutes.
That's massive.
This is our house-made
Sriracha crema.
Gonna hit that
with a little bit of olive oil
and some fresh
chopped chives.
Mmm!
A good amount of meat,
great texture.
[ Both mumble ]
I like
it's a little crunchy.
The American cheese
is what makes it all fly.
And then then Sriracha
dipping sauce -- point on, man.
Mmm!
It really does have
a "Philly cheesesteak
in a pretzel" feel.
That's out of bounds, man.
-Philly pretzel.
-Delicious, moist.
Shaved steak inside is awesome.
The flavors are amazing,
and I love the sauce.
The menu in general is far more
than a pretzel place.
MAN:
They have a great raw bar.
They have a lot of
oyster-oriented seafood dishes.
The oyster chowder.
I got to try the chowder,
by the way.
Oh, yeah.
Here we got our fresh
oyster chowder for you.
-This is your head chef?
-Mm-hmm.
What is this fritter on top?
That is a freshly fried
oyster.
I like the fried oyster on top,
nice tender potatoes.
Excellent chowder.
What the Driftwood does best
is a twist
on a classic American dish.
Here's that shepherd's pie
for table 5.
MAN: Has short rib in it instead
of, you know, ground beef.
It's really good.
What are we making now,
homey?
Braised short ribs
for the short-rib shepherd pie.
Short-rib shepherd pie.
Hey, oh, now.
Here, now.
Add some oil in the pan.
Take our short ribs.
Gonna hit them with a little bit
of salt and pepper.
There we go.
And now that these short ribs
are seared off,
we're gonna put them
in this hotel pan,
and we're gonna add
our mirepoix
plus a little bit
of fresh garlic.
Tomato paste
and fresh herb mixture.
Mix that up a bit.
Deglaze the pan
with Harpoon Irish Stout,
our burgundy wine,
and some water.
All right,
so, take the braising liquid
over the top
of the short ribs.
Let that sear off
in the oven.
250 for 5 hours.
Now we're making the...
Root vegetable puree that gets
topped on the shepherd's pie.
Oh, really?
Russet potatoes.
Some sweet potato.
-Parsnips.
White onion.
Fresh garlic.
Little olive oil.
Seasoning
with salt and pepper.
So, slow-roast this down.
250 for how long?
-Three hours.
Now we're gonna add
our roasted root vegetables
to the Robot Coupe.
We're gonna add some butter,
heavy whipping cream,
and salt and pepper to taste.
All right. Hit it.
We got our braised short ribs
out of the oven.
Very nicely done.
Look at that, huh?
Nothing wrong with that.
-All right?
-Just chug that down right now.
Now we're gonna pull
the meat out.
Strain the vegetables.
Puree that up.
That's gonna be the base layer.
We're gonna build a nice layer
of the short rib here.
Pureed root vegetables
gonna get the top layer.
The au jus that we have topped
right onto it.
In the oven how long?
450 for about 12 minutes.
Got it.
So, we got some locally sourced
microgreens.
Fried shallots.
The meat
is super tender.
I love the braising liquid
right at the top
'cause that adds
even more depth.
Very simple,
very straightforward,
very comforting.
That's an all-American dish
right there.
Shepherd's pie.
The shredded short rib
brings it home.
Just it makes it a little
different and a little unique.
Really like the parsnips
and the roasted potatoes.
Tory, I got your Philly pretzel
for the raw bar.
This is the kind of place
I wanted to find,
where all the locals go,
where they hang out,
serve great food,
lots of good cocktails,
a lot of craft beer.
This is when you go on vacation,
you get into a town,
you're like,
"Hey, where do you go?"
This is the place you go.
-Nicely done.
-Thank you.
FIERI:
Up next, in Minnesota...
This would make you move
to Minneapolis.
...a neighborhood pub
rising from the ashes...
There you go.
Look at that!
...and taking their menu
to new heights.
This is elevated bar food
big-time.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in the Powderhorn neighborhood
of Minneapolis, Minnesota.
Now, listen, everybody loves
their favorite gastropub,
but here in this area,
these folks,
the neighbors, the fans
love the joint so much
that after it burnt down,
they helped raise money
to reopen the joint.
This is Buster's on 28th.
Got a Walleye Rachel
with sweet potatoes.
This is the definition
of a neighborhood bar.
-We got a turkey burger.
-This place is like a super pub.
It's just got great food,
great beers, and great people.
FIERI:
That's the kind of love
that owners Joel Hall
and Mike Steer hoped for
when they opened this joint
in 2007.
But then things got interesting.
There was a big bad storm
back in 2013.
The hood ignited.
I've been there.
I've had a restaurant burn.
The neighborhood got behind it,
and you finally reopened.
Did you think
it would actually happen?
It was pretty dark there
for a little while.
They closed for a year, and it
was the longest year of my life.
FIERI: Even Chef Dave Steffens
was counting the days
until he could get back
to rockin' out
his own take on pub grub.
Gyro burger with coleslaw.
The menu here is not what I
would consider typical bar food.
Braised beef
with salt-and-vinegar chips.
It's beef cooked in beer.
It's awesome.
Just what you expect
and even more.
All right, so,
what are we making first?
Beer-braised beef.
Start with brisket.
Yep, we're gonna just break
her down into 4x4 cubes.
Make it easier for all the beer
to get to all the meat.
And then we'll go ahead
and season up --
a little salt and pepper,
little garlic powder in there.
Then we'll just give it
a quick rub through.
And then we top that off
with some of our
julienne onions here.
Mix in lots of garlic cloves.
And, of course,
our local beer of choice.
Heavy stout.
We're gonna wrap it.
In the oven. How long?
8 hours
in a 500-degree oven.
So this is gonna cook down
to nada.
What are we making now?
Salt-and-vinegar
potato chips.
Idaho potato.
Soak them in water,
pulling out the starch.
Gonna add a little bit
of our vinegar.
Salt.
Go ahead
and just add it to that.
We marinate it
for 12 to 24 hours.
Really?
We pull it out and fry it
straight to order.
So, we got it all
nice and cooked down.
Look at that.
I'll have some of that.
[ Laughs ]
So, then we go ahead
and separate our beef
from our sauce here.
Shred this bad boy up.
Strain off any excess fat.
And then we go ahead
and buzz that up.
Go ahead and add our sauce
back in here.
Let this kind of marry.
Smells great.
Got our chips here --
nice and crispy.
Take a little bit
of our lovely beef here.
Ah, those are good!
And our roasted red pepper
cream cheese.
And that's our beer-braised beef
with our homemade chips.
That says swimsuit.
♪♪
Is there anything here?
Where is it?
Thank you.
It's the director of the show.
That will make you want to sell
your home and move in.
Hell yes.
Bomb, rock-star chips.
Oh!
I come to a place
like Buster's,
that's the kind of sandwich
I expect.
Can't go wrong.
Brother,
you can't go any more right.
That is fantastic.
Nice job.
Braised beef with
salt-and-vinegar potato chips.
It's a mouthful
of deliciousness.
It's just overflowing with beef.
It's got a great tangy sauce.
It's just yummy.
There you go.
Look at that!
So, one of my ways to find
the greatest places to eat
in a town
is to ask somebody
that owns a limo company.
This is my buddy Gus.
What do you think?
It's awesome,
and it's what you want
when you sit
in a bar like this.
And the first thing I noticed
was all of the beers.
I think they only have
like 32 on tap.
Oh, look at that.
It's Chef Pauly from Nye's.
One of my all-time faves.
Rumor has it
Nye's is closing.
It is.
It's very sad.
How would you describe
this joint to people?
This is not bar food.
This is great food.
I got a steak sandwich
with onion rings.
It's awesome.
It's got this blue cheese sauce.
Just scrumptious.
What are we making now?
A little bit of our blue cheese
dressing for our steak sandwich.
We're gonna go ahead
and throw one nice
little shallot in there.
Now we're adding
our garlic.
Little salt,
little pepper.
'Cause they're
in effect?
Always, always.
Got our blue cheese here.
We got a little buttermilk
going in there, also.
Give this a little
pulse here.
Then we're gonna go ahead
and add that back to the mayo.
And then we got a little bit
of our local hot sauce here
from Minnesota.
Stir that up.
Let it come together.
Blue cheese dressing.
Now we make
the steak sandwich.
Now we do.
So, we got our top cap here
off of our sirloin.
This is called
the culotte.
We just trim it up
real quick,
and we go ahead and we portion
into a 6-ounce portion.
We'll go ahead
and butterfly this.
Open. We'll give her a nice
little sliced julienne here.
You got a lot of passion
about this.
It's very evident.
It's good.
We take the sliced meat,
and we go ahead and throw it
right on our flattop here.
Got a little
salt and pepper.
Seasoning blend, of course,
as always.
Got a little bit of our cooked
bacon here, all julienne,
and some nice caramelized onions
going on top of that, as well.
Toasted bun here.
Beautiful steak sandwich
coming at you.
You're small
on the portions, son.
We make sure
you don't go home hungry
and you got something
for tomorrow.
Our homemade blue cheese
that we did earlier.
And some of those
fresh fried chips.
-No, you didn't.
-Yes, sir.
And then we'll go ahead
and throw
our house-made onion rings
on there for you.
This is screaming
the hunch.
Ah, boy.
Should serve this
in a kiddie pool.
[ Muffled ]
That is good.
[ Laughs ]
I mean, when you talk about
a higher-level steak sandwich...
Mmm!
That one's rock star.
This would make you
move to Minneapolis.
I don't even
want to eat anymore.
I just want to take a picture
of it with me.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
Steak sandwich.
It's just awesome.
It's juicy. It's good.
Very tender,
and it's just succulent.
Shrimp taco going in the window.
I've always wanted to find a bar
that I could call my bar.
I found it.
♪♪
I've been to funky
little neighborhood joints
all over the country, man.
This is elevated bar food
big-time.
Awesome job.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
We got 350
on the fryer today.
[ Southern accent ]
Today on the fryer, we got 350.
350.
350 once. 350 twice.
All right, 350.
[ Laughter ]