Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
-This trip...
-Tell me!
...we're digging
into killer dishes...
Holy moly.
...and grabbing
a fistful of flavor.
That's awesome.
In Bayport, Minnesota...
I think
I've met my match.
...a family-run
barbecue joint...
Way to live it, man.
...all about doing it
their way.
It's kind of your world.
We're just all rotating
around it right now.
In Falmouth, Massachusetts...
I'll take any of that.
...a cozy New England café...
Small portions,
I can tell.
...going South
for the bomb breakfast.
So, I'm all the way
in Cape Cod having Tex-Mex.
And in Denver, Colorado...
Do you like it?
Little more than like.
...an empanada empire.
If you look in the dictionary
under "empanada,"
that's what it looks like.
...that's enough
to bring a tear to my eye.
Ay!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here on South Broadway
about 10 minutes
from downtown Denver, Colorado,
to check out a joint
with a great story.
Now, check this out.
The chef, she came
from Buenos Aires, Argentina,
12 years ago.
Now, she's got an empanada
empire.
This is Maria Empanada.
Carprese.
Nothing compares
to Maria Empanada.
You really feel like you're
in a little part
of Buenos Aires.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
You can feel
that it's made with passion.
FIERI: And determination, all
from owner Lorena Cantarovici.
So, how did you
get from Buenos Aires to here?
I just grabbed $300,
a backpack,
and three words in English --
"Hi, hello, and ciao."
Ciao?
Ciao is not English.
And how did
the empanada empire start?
Because I miss it a lot,
and I didn't find any empanada
here in Denver,
so I need to make it.
And does she ever.
Since opening the joint,
named after her mom, in 2011,
she now cranks out --
get this -- up to 1,500 a day.
You would think there's an army
back in the kitchen
making empanadas.
How authentic
are these empanadas?
They could learn
in Argentina.
That authentic?
Beef empanadas.
I love the beef empanada.
MAN:
Ground beef, onions, peppers,
seasoning wrapped
in, like, a turnover pastry.
It's amazing.
-So?
-We're going to make the dough,
and we will put
some salt here.
-Baking powder.
-And then margarine.
-All-purpose flour?
-Yes.
Okay.
Now, we will put some eggs
and water.
This is going to mix up
how long?
Around 10 minutes.
We let it rest.
Rub the baby.
What'd you just say?
My baby.
Okay,
so now you take the baby?
Okay, and then we take it
to la máquina.
This is
the empanada express?
Yes.
It keeps disappearing
to the end of the table.
Oh, don't worry. Don't worry.
It will come back.
You like it?
That's awesome.
Look how beautiful it is.
And we do like this.
And that's empanada dough.
And now we're going to make
the...?
-Filling.
-The filling.
This is corn oil, okay?
And then we put
some onions.
We have red pepper.
-Okay, next?
-Ground beef.
Who taught you to make
empanadas?
My mom.
So, we put some salt here.
Look at this.
Pepper.
Crushed red pepper.
Comino.
Muy bien.
And this is pimentón,
Spanish paprika.
-Not spicy?
-No spice.
We are going
to let it cool.
Okay,
what are we going to make?
-Chimichurri.
Sí.
Parsley, red pepper.
-Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-What, what, what, what?
This is chimichurri,
with red pepper?
The authentic one.
Oh.
Okay, come back.
-Garlic.
-I like garlic.
-Okay.
-I love garlic.
-Salt and pepper.
-Pepper.
-Then we have some pimentón.
-Pimentón.
-Sí.
-Okay.
Then we have crushed red pepper.
Da, da, da!
[ Stammers ]
Vinegar, oregano,
and olive oil.
Beautiful olive oil.
For how long do we let
this set up?
-3 to 4 days.
-Now we make the empanadas.
Let's do empanadas.
Vamos.
We grab this
that we made before.
We put some olives,
some of the filling
that we made.
So, each one
gets this fold over.
-Yes, yes.
-[ Whistles ]
If you look in the dictionary
under "empanada,"
that's what it looks like.
That's impressive.
Little egg wash.
Exactly.
We bake 'em
at what temperature?
375. 10 to 12 minutes.
So, empanadas are ready.
-Are you ready?
-Listo.
Do you like it?
Little more than like.
Aw. I like it, too.
There's a subtlety.
A subtle flavor,
a subtle texture,
just a uniqueness.
Not too spicy.
Got to have
the chimichurri.
It's light, little flavor,
little crust, simple.
That's what an empanada's
supposed to be.
-Excellent job.
-Thank you.
Very good.
Easy to eat, great flavor.
It's delicately done,
very savory.
The chimichurri sauce
is the ultimate complement.
Can I get
the beef classico, please?
MAN:
When you look at that case,
you just want to dive in
and eat 'em all.
You don't want to leave.
-Okay. Thank you.
-Thank you.
Was it always this big?
Was it here at this location?
No, I did have
a very small location.
It doesn't even matter
what she's talking about,
all of a sudden,
it became dramatic.
Then what happened?
You want to really hear
what happened?
Oh, yes, I do.
Tell me!
-Are you ready?
-Ay!
We just decided
that the business grow a lot,
and we needed to move.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI:
But it's a happy ending,
'cause now she's got a space
to make all the empanada
she wants, and more.
-Tarta Analia.
-It's amazing.
When we come back,
we are going to make...?
-Tarta.
-Tarta what?
Analia.
Every time I come here,
and I eat the tarta,
-I feel like I'm home.
-We'll see you in a little bit.
Hanging out with the Empanada
Queen in Denver, Colorado.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" here
in Denver, Colorado,
hanging out
with the Empanada Princess
with her empanada empire,
and we're at Maria Empanada.
She makes 13 different types
of empanadas.
But now we're going
to make a...?
Tarta. [ Laughs ]
There's not that many R's
in it, really.
Okay, Tarta Analia.
It has bold medley
of different veggies,
Nice cream cheese at the bottom,
and it's got a flaky crust.
It's amazing.
So this is going to be a tarta
stuffed with fresh vegetables.
-Yes, yes.
-Okay.
So, we have the butternut
squash right here,
carrots, the zucchinis.
-Eggplant, yeah?
-Eggplant, yes.
The red onions.
Salt and pepper.
And some olive oil.
How long
we going to roast this?
30 minutes.
So, roasted veggies.
And now some basil.
Basil. All right.
Yes,
and the green onions.
And look at the color here.
Isn't that great?
-Beautiful.
-Now, we need the dough.
Let's try to take
all the air that is --
-On the sides.
-On the side. Yes.
And then we put
some cream cheese.
Cream cheese
is Argentinean?
-Queso crema.
A little queso crema.
A little bit of Parmesano.
And now we can put
the filling here.
-Need more cheese?
-I need more Parmesan.
There you go.
Beautiful colors.
Now we make these little...
Of course, you have to do
some little disco dance
when it goes
all the way around.
-Yes.
-Okay.
So, we bake this off.
What temperature?
425 for 50 minutes.
-There you go.
-And a little basil on top.
That reminds me of almost
like a calzone.
Nice, bright,
fresh vegetables
that keeps that little bit
of cream cheese, a little bit
of acid at the bottom,
and a little bit of fat,
and you're able to eat it almost
like you're eating a sandwich.
People dig it.
Tarta Analia, please.
It's light and delicate.
I could do a few of these.
You can't wait to get
to your table and dive into it.
Nothing compares
to Maria Empanada.
People ask me about
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives,"
and are like,
"What are the places?"
This is it.
You got a character,
you got a story,
and you got great food.
Thank you.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Bayport, Minnesota...
Look at this.
...smoking, blues,
and barbecue...
I give you all the props,
all the respect.
...just the way
this family likes it.
This is maybe one
of the more unique styles
on "Triple D" I've seen.
You see, even when it's raining,
I'm out looking for
great "Triple D" joints for you.
I'm here in Bayport, Minnesota,
right on the Wisconsin border --
Little town,
about 3,400 people --
to check out a barbecue joint
that's run by the family only.
There's no employees.
Their motto is,
"We aren't for everyone."
This is Bayport BBQ.
♪ Come on in and sit down ♪
♪ Check out
what we got going on ♪
MAN: It's one of the best
barbecue places
I have ever been in the U.S.
Great food, great music.
MAN:
It's amazing to have it here
in the small town of Bayport.
Couple bars, couple churches,
and one great barbecue place.
I have more cornbread
coming up.
The whole family works here.
FIERI: Led by mom Kristen
and dad Chris Johnson,
who traded
in a buttoned-down corporate gig
to do their own thing in 2010.
I'm a pretty independent
kind of guy.
Our music is different,
our food is different,
our bar's different.
We have a full
liquor license,
but we choose just to sell beer,
wine, white whiskey.
You don't sell French fries
because...?
Just choose not to.
Holy moly.
You know,
we aren't for everyone.
And you'd better be okay
with fetching your own food,
I mean, literally,
right from the kitchen.
They have a buffet line.
And you can go through
as many times as you want.
I'll have more brisket
in one second.
I want Chris to tuck me
in bed at night
under a blanket
made of this brisket.
Should we make some rub
for the brisket?
I don't know, can we?
Okay, let's get into it.
So, we do start
with salt and pepper.
Season salt, onion powder,
garlic powder,
granulated onion, paprika.
-Cayenne.
-Red pepper flakes.
Little cumin.
Okay.
We do a full choice brisket,
-Just generously apply it on.
-Not going to trim it.
-No, we want the fat.
-Yeah, we do.
And what kind of wood
we smoking with?
White oak.
About 13 hours, 250.
Ooh. Running hot.
-Yeah, it works for us.
-Everything does.
It's kind of your world.
We're just all rotating
around it right now.
Let's make some bread.
We're going to make
the bread.
It's a very simple recipe.
-Just water.
-Okay.
Yeast, salt,
high-gluten bread flour.
Like pizza-dough flour.
-And that's it.
-That's it.
It goes into a grease tub.
Let it rest for 10, 12 hours.
Should we shape
some loaves?
I don't know.
You tell me.
We'll oil a pan.
Do people come here
and buy a loaf of bread?
Yes.
Our bread is very popular.
That cornmeal's the kicker.
Shape the loaf
and put it in the pan.
-This'll poof again.
-Another couple hours.
And then a little more
cornmeal on top.
And then we bake it in the oven.
What temp?
425 for about 15 minutes.
-That's it.
It's like a ciabatta.
Oh, that's awesome.
So, we do this into thirds.
Look at this.
We do over a half pound.
[ Whistles ]
Slaw.
Bread and butter pickles.
Okay. That's it.
That's it.
Very simply done.
I love the bark,
I love the smoke.
It's true, real smoke.
It's not super-pull-apart.
It should have
some texture.
Of course, you haven't seen
me stop eating any of this.
-That bread, it's outstanding.
-Yeah.
I give you all the props
for doing it your way.
I think I've met my match.
The brisket is really good.
Thick and it's juicy.
I always, always get the bread.
It's just delicious.
WOMAN:
It's really a fun place
to just come and hang out
with your friends,
have some good barbecue,
listen to live music.
-How are the blues here?
-Underground.
-Underground blues.
-Yeah.
It sets it apart
from any other barbecue joint.
MAN: Blues that you
wouldn't hear anywhere else
but either down south
or here in Bayport, Minnesota.
And you get to feed yourself
this amazing barbecue.
Pulled pork is super tender,
really juicy.
All-over-your-face delicious.
-Pork butt time.
-Yeah.
So, the same dry rub we had.
Same rub for everything.
All right, in the smoker.
What temp?
250, overnight.
About 13 hours.
Okay.
-We're making barbecue sauce.
-There we go.
We smoke the tomatoes
and onions.
Okay.
And we puree it
with some tomato juice.
Now we'll strain the puree,
-and add the other ingredients.
-Okay.
-Ketchup, Worcestershire.
-Worcestershire.
Where'd you learn
to make the barbecue sauce?
Trial and error.
At a place
you used to work?
Our house rub,
chipotles in adobo sauce.
Okay.
-Honey.
-Darling.
Wildflower.
Chickapea.
Minced garlic.
-A lot of it.
-Hot sauce.
-Lemon juice.
-Okay.
Apple cider vinegar.
Yellow mustard.
-And brown sugar.
-Really?
So, this will go on the stovetop
for a few hours.
All right,
so the butts be done.
Look at that bark.
All right.
Do you want to serve
your own platter?
Oh, I would love to.
Tender pork, nice butt,
good smoke.
Right in the realm
of pulled pork.
Love that bark.
Little bit of sweet,
little bit of tang,
a lot of tomato, texture.
Really good smoke
in the barbecue.
-I'd eat that all day long.
-Thank you.
Pulled pork is super juicy
and delicious.
MAN: Put it on a sandwich
with the coleslaw
and all the fixings,
and 10 napkins later,
you're full.
The family works together to
make it a great place to visit.
This is maybe one
of the more unique styles
on "Triple D" I've seen.
You're living it
your way, man.
-I got to give you props for it.
-Thanks.
Way to like it, man.
FIERI: Up next...
a Falmouth, Massachusetts,
café...
I like this.
That's like patting your stomach
and rubbing your head.
...stacking up
the sandwiches...
This is what
you're looking for.
...and putting a righteous spin
on rancheros.
Real deal. Great job.
Delicious dish.
I'm just like you.
I roll into a town, I'm looking
for a "Triple D" joint.
And long before
there was "Triple D,"
I was here in this town --
Falmouth, Massachusetts.
I was ready to catch a ferry to
head over to Martha's Vineyard.
I was looking for a place
to eat.
Man, I wish this joint
had been open.
This is Parkside Market.
Green eggs and ham.
I would come here any day
for breakfast or lunch.
John Alden.
Feels like homegrown,
local flare.
WOMAN:
It's a very hearty restaurant.
They're just a wonderful,
hardworking group of people.
FIERI: That group
is husband and wife team
Stephen and Susan Bowen,
and their partner
and chef Anthony Carroll.
How do you all
know each other?
-How did this come together?
-We all met in Florida, working.
-Who's from here?
-No one.
FIERI: But the town's definitely
welcomed these transplants
since they opened the joint
in 2013.
Local and organic,
everything's delicious.
When you're feeling like you
need a good breakfast feast,
-this is the place.
-Tex-Mex with bacon.
The Tex-Mex is very good.
Homemade corn patty on
a pico sauce, black bean humus.
It's what I come here for.
Kind of like our version
of huevos rancheros.
"Huevos" means eggs.
We're not doing eggs
for you today.
I can do some sausage
or some bacon on there.
I'll take any of that.
All right, let's get into it.
We're going to start
with our homemade corn cakes.
We've got our sugar,
pureed corn kernels,
vegetable oil.
-Okay.
-Some water.
And blended eggs.
-And then we'll add --
-All the dry.
We have cornmeal.
Our masa harina.
Corn kernels,
cheddar Jack cheese.
And some kosher salt,
and our cold chopped butter.
Just going to mix
our wet real quick,
-and our dry at the same time.
-I like this.
That's like patting your stomach
and rubbing your head.
So, I'm all the way
in Cape Cod having Tex-Mex.
From a guy
who's from Missouri.
-This is ready to rock.
-Ready to rock 'n' roll.
Got it.
All right.
We're going to make
our black bean humus.
Start with some black beans,
garbanzo beans.
We'll do some garlic,
as well.
Little salt and pepper.
And a little oil.
All right,
plating our Tex-Mex.
We'll start with our
hot tomato sauce and pico.
-Same portions, I can tell.
-Oh, yeah.
And then we'll do
our corn cakes.
-Black bean humus.
And then just for Guy,
we're going to do sausage
and bacon.
And finally,
we top with our avocado,
and there you go.
Yeah.
[ Grunts ]
I really like the texture
on the cornmeal cake.
The warm pico on top of it
pulls everything together.
My favorite honestly,
of all of it, though,
is the black bean humus.
Mm. Real deal. Great job.
Delicious dish.
For you, the Tex-Mex.
It's just a great combo.
WOMAN: It's my ultimate
breakfast go-to.
Fantastic.
-Cobb salad.
-I love Parkside
because their food
is really fresh and delicious.
It's a lot like Waterside
on Martha's Vineyard.
FIERI:
Yep, that's right,
Parkside has a sister restaurant
right across the water.
Go from one to the other,
-and the consistency is there.
-French Quarter.
I work
at another sandwich store.
Wait a second, you work
at another sandwich place,
but you eat here?
This is my favorite spot.
And cab sandwich is my favorite.
Cab with fries, pick it up.
Chicken, some ranch dressing,
crispy bacon, avocado.
So, everything I love.
What's this for?
What's the dish?
This is for our cab.
Chicken almost burger?
Chicken, avocado, bacon.
Chicken avocado. Oh!
So close.
So, we just start with
all-natural breasts of chicken,
a little salt,
pepper, granulated garlic,
and then we hit it
with some oil.
Rub it in.
And then thyme and tarragon.
-In the oven. What temp?
-350 for 30 to 40 minutes.
-All right.
-Now we're going to slice it?
Yeah.
We like it pretty thin,
just so
we can pile it high.
We're going to do some ranch
on the bottom.
-Okay.
-Sliced chicken.
Vermont cheddar, bacon.
Goes in the convection oven
for us.
-Melt all that.
-Melt all that and activate
-the fat in that bacon.
-Okay.
Now we're going
to add the avocado.
Finish it off
with the house-made ranch.
Slice her.
Hand-cut fries.
Nicely done.
If it's going to be
a simple sandwich like that,
you've got to put everything
together.
So you delivered.
The avocado definitely
plays the key into it.
The roasted chicken's nice,
not too dry.
Great bread, little bit
of bacon, some cheese.
-Nice job, brother.
-Thank you.
Two cabs with hand-cut fries.
They're great.
The sandwiches are always great.
Gentlemen,
first let me say me say
thank you very much
for your service.
-Have you had the cab before?
-I have had it.
-What do you like about it?
-Everything about it.
Garcia over here,
he's the cook on your cutter.
Is it as good as his?
Better watch
what you say right now.
I'm going to keep
my mouth shut on that one.
-Picking up, please.
-Come to Parkside.
I promise you,
you will not be disappointed,
and you will leave here full
and satisfied.
You call yourself
Parkside Market.
This is what
you're looking for.
-Chef, great job, buddy.
-Thank you.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking you next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Can have it in the case,
but they are going to be warm.
In the case is warm, too?
-Yes.
-You hold 'em warm?
Yes.
I wasn't arguing.
I was just asking.
[ Laughter ]