Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
This looks like
a made-for-TV movie.
...we're cruising from brisket
to biscuits...
Oh, my gosh, that's good.
...with some dynamite detours
in between.
What's that city you always go
to with all the good tastes?
That's Flavortown 101,
ain't it?
In Fort Collins, Colorado...
What do you mean I have
cauliflower ear?
...a funky neighborhood café...
-Rah!
-[ Laughs ]
...cranking out some crazy
culinary creations.
Was it a dare
to make this?
In Atlanta, Georgia...
Whoa!
Ho-ho!
...a champion chef...
She won "Chopped," what was it,
season 8, 9, 10, 11?
You won all of them.
-Season 8.
...scratch making wake-you-up
winners.
You can't make that up.
You know that.
Then, a quick drive south...
Bring it, doctor.
...for a twin-brother tag
team...
That's weird.
...going way beyond
the barbecue.
That's all throttle,
no bottle, man.
That is just getting it done.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Atlanta,
Georgia,
and I am looking for what?
Exactly.
Some real-deal barbecue.
-So --
-You know what it is, Guy,
with this crate 502
in here,
we just got to bump
the timing up a little bit.
That's all it is.
So, you call
your buddy Rutledge,
who knows a lot about cars
and a ton about barbecue.
-This is the real deal?
-This is the real deal.
This is
Fox Bros. Bar-B-Q.
Smoke wings up in the window.
Fox Bros. is probably the best
barbecue I've ever had.
Whole-rack plate up.
Just one of those places
you've got to come to.
Pork plate up in the window.
Run it.
It's legit Texas barbecue.
And they nailed it.
FIERI: "They" are
Jonathan and Justin Fox,
just your everyday
barbecue-loving
Texan twin brothers.
How'd you guys get this started?
We pretty much just started
cooking in our backyard
for our friends.
FIERI: And in 2007,
they moved from backyard parties
into a massive business.
We smoke probably 10,000 pounds
of pork and brisket a week.
FIERI:
Are there no other restaurants?
Are we on an island?
-Pretty much.
-Wow.
It's that good.
Hey, you put good food out
there, people come.
FIERI: Which includes a big fan
of what these twins
are turning out -- my buddy,
"Top Gear" host Rutledge Wood.
It is the best barbecue in
Atlanta, hands down.
Fox Bros. burger up
in the window.
The Fox Bros. burger
is a mouthful.
It's sort of a misnomer
to call it a burger.
It's not a burger at all.
It's brisket.
You can tell
it's just smoked
all day on the hickory,
and your hair smells like it
when you leave,
and that's how you know
you're at a good barbecue joint.
All right, let's get after it.
This is certified
Angus beef.
Just trim down this fat
just a little bit.
When you're using CAB --
certified Angus beef --
you're starting
with great clay.
[ Righteous Brothers'
"Unchained Melody" plays ]
I get it.
Yeah, 'cause you love
the movie "Ghost."
I totally get the pottery
reference.
-That was a great one, man.
-[ Laughter ]
You're really good at this.
You are really good at this.
Oh...
What are we doing now?
Now we're gonna season
our brisket
with our
salt-and-pepper seasoning.
Brisket with
salt and pepper.
That is as Texas
as it comes.
Now we're gonna go
to the smoker?
-Now we're gonna go
to the smoker.
-Great.
We cook it overnight, 10 to 12
hours, at 200, 205 degrees.
Basically, as low
as it'll go.
-Yep.
-Let's go.
Okay, Jonathan, what are
we gonna start with --
Who?
[ Eerie music plays ]
-That's Justin.
-Come on, get it right.
They look
totally different.
That's weird.
[ Whooshes ]
So, now what are
we into?
Our homemade barbecue sauce.
Bring it, doctor.
We got a homemade ketchup,
we got some vinegar --
-Distilled white?
-Yep.
-Next up?
-Hot sauce.
-Anybody particular?
-Texas Pete, of course.
-There you go.
-Little Texas love.
Made in Carolina.
Texas Pete, made in Carolina,
used in Atlanta?
-Yeah.
-Makes sense. Next up?
Black pepper.
-Granulated garlic.
-Blackstrap molasses?
-Yes.
-[ Whistles ] Okay.
-Brown sugar.
-Mmm.
Worcestershire sauce.
-Chili powder.
-Mmm.
-[ Laughs ]
Was that silent grunting?
Yeah, that's what we do
in the South.
When you like something,
you just go, "Mmm."
-Onion powder.
-And last but not least?
-Salt.
Just let it come up to temp and
simmer for about 30, 40 minutes.
Beautiful.
What are we making now?
We're making pimento cheese.
Let's get into it.
Cheddar cheese.
Pepper Jack cheese.
You know what, if you're
gonna try it,
I just feel like I
should try it, too.
You better get
right in there.
Mayonnaise.
Pimentos.
A little pepper.
And, for some heat,
Cayenne pepper.
Mix it up by hand.
Let's make a patty
for our Fox Bros. burger.
All right,
let's make the burger.
So, we're gonna take this
brisket...
Oh, my gosh, that's good.
Get after it, Zorro.
We got some of our house-made
jalapeño mayo right here.
Pimento-cheese patty.
And we're gonna take this
beautiful thing
and throw it
under the salamander.
We got to hurry up
and get this burger out
before Rutledge eats
all of the other brisket that --
[ Clatters ]
-Rutledge!
-I'm sorry.
Here we go.
Hit it.
Take our toasted bun.
We got some
of our peppered bacon,
a couple pickles, tomato, onion.
That's a chopped-beef sandwich,
called it a burger.
-Called it a burger.
-I like it.
Oh!
That's a great burger.
You just, like,
cleaning up over there
like a lion
that just ate a gazelle.
I don't know
what happened.
I -- I went after mine.
It's super-tender brisket.
When you chop that brisket up,
-you get a chance
to incorporate that fat.
-Yeah.
So it makes it even
a little bit more unctuous.
But adding the pimento cheese
and adding the veggies
on top of it
brings that burger element
to it.
Mmm.
That's Fox Bros.
right there.
Damn, man!
Come on.
All right, that's
full-speed, man.
That's all throttle,
no bottle, man.
That is just getting it done.
Fox Bros. burger.
This is really good, juicy,
savory brisket
that everybody wants
to come back for.
We get cravings all the time.
It's like, "How soon can
we get back to Atlanta
and get back to Fox Bros.?"
I've got some chicken-fried ribs
for you.
Nobody does ribs like they do
here at the Fox Bros.
When we come back, it's time to
have some chicken-fried ribs.
Chicken-fried steak,
chicken-fried ribs,
-chicken-fried chicken...
-And Rutledge Gump.
See you in a minute.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: "Triple D" is cooking
low and slow
at Fox Bros. barbecue
in Atlanta, Georgia.
The Fox brothers are twin
brothers.
They're from Texas.
How do you describe
your barbecue?
Well, we call it a mix
of where we're at
and where we're from.
So, Southern-style, but...
-Texas roots.
-Yeah.
FIERI: And another southern boy
is joining me at this joint --
car-racing analyst and
barbecue-loving machine
Rutledge Wood.
What do you think makes it
so great?
The stuff is smoked
so long and so low.
Everything is just
the best of the best here.
Chicken-fried rib
up in the window.
Chicken-fried ribs.
Is this an Atlanta staple?
I think it's a Fox Bros.
staple.
I've never had it
anywhere else.
It's a rib that's been
chicken-fried in a batter.
It's the perfect
Southern snack.
FIERI: Okay.
St. Louis-cut spare rib.
We're gonna make
our dry rub.
Okay.
Let's get at this.
Salt, black pepper,
onion powder,
garlic powder,
a little chili powder.
-Okay.
-Paprika.
What is this, Rutledge?
Before he does it?
Ooh. This looks like a --
can I try it?
This is one of my favorite
things you do.
Hold on, let me see if I can do
it the way Guy does it.
-No, no, no.
-Mmm. I taste like a -- mmm --
little bit of --
a little bit of cumin,
a little bit of -- mmm --
is that coffee?
What is -- I don't
know what that is.
What is that?
Ancho chili?
Yeah.
A little ancho chili.
And we just mix it all up.
We're gonna rub it down
really good.
Flip the other side?
-Rub it down as well.
-Okay.
We're gonna rub it
with brown sugar.
-How long we
gonna let it rest?
-An hour or two.
All right. This is gonna go
in the smoker how long?
We're gonna cook this at 225
for about four hours.
Okay.
All right, Justin,
what are we --
[ Eerie music plays ]
This is getting ridiculous.
I'm not Justin.
Jonathan, goatee,
Justin, clean-shaven.
It's 'cause I'm
from not around here.
What are we doing next?
-We're making --
-Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
I'm not playing these
shenanigans anymore.
Go ahead, hit it.
This is what we're gonna soak
the ribs in.
-Okay.
-We got a little bit
of buttermilk,
a little bit of hot sauce.
We got some eggs.
And some more
of the rub.
And we got some dry rub.
We're going to do
a double-bone cut.
So, it's a big,
extra-meaty rib.
So, you don't have
the rib here
and you don't have the rib
there...
You get plenty of meat
on both sides.
...but you get
the meat of both. Got it.
-And before we dredge?
-Got our flour.
We're gonna season it up
with some dry rub.
-Okay.
-And we're gonna take our rib,
dunk it...
Oh, a double.
-Double dunker? [Whistles]
-Double dunker.
You know, I've watched
this show a million times,
but when you're here,
it's like real work.
And we're gonna throw it
in the fryer.
All right, till they get all
nice and brown and crusty?
Golden-brown and delicious.
If a rib ain't good enough,
we chicken-fry it.
Everything is better
chicken-fried.
Now we're gonna serve it up
with our Fox Bros.
white barbecue sauce.
And there you have
a chicken-fried rib.
♪♪
I think I can just punch
my ticket to --
what's that city you always go
to with all the good tastes?
That's Flavortown 101,
ain't it?
There you go.
That's it.
Wow, that's good.
Little crunchification
on the outside
of some of that tender rib.
I love the funky sauce.
A chicken-fried rib.
-Chicken-fried.
-Whoo!
Zac Brown
would love that.
You know, everything,
he's about chicken-fried.
Zac, you hungry?
That's you, brother,
all day long.
Come and get it.
I have some
chicken-fried ribs.
Thank you very much.
The ribs were huge.
Just as tender as you
could ever want a rib.
When you're gonna get the real
deal on somebody's food,
you got to go
to childhood friends.
Here's my buddy James.
Ange and I grew up down
the street from each other.
I mean, I've had a lot of
barbecue here in Georgia,
and I have to say,
I've never had better.
Tomminator up.
Whenever I come here, I feel
like I'm back in Texas.
Are you gonna
finish that, Guy?
That's all you?
You gonna finish that?
I'm just gonna get this --
I just --
I don't know how long
this show is, but...
-Mmm.
-Y'all come back now...
-Ya hear?
-Ha ha! Peace.
Coming up, we're kicking it
across town...
Oh, I like that.
...for the bomb chicken
and biscuits...
I dig it.
...and the lights-out lox.
I love the attitude.
I love the refined simplicity.
♪♪
You know, I am always
on the quest.
I'm looking for the best brisket
in Texas.
I'm looking for the best chowder
in New England,
the best tacos in San Diego.
So when I come to Atlanta,
Georgia,
I'm looking for the bomb
biscuits,
and I hear these people own it.
This is Buttermilk Kitchen.
Noodle omelet.
The food at Buttermilk is
wholesome, it's fresh.
It's farm-to-table.
It's a good feeling to know
that that the owner, the chef,
is from Atlanta and gets all of
her ingredients
from local areas.
FIERI: And if you think this
chef looks familiar,
there's a reason for that.
She won "Chopped," what was it,
season 8, 9, 10, 11?
You won all of them.
-Season 8. Yes, sir.
-Season 8.
FIERI: Then, in 2012,
Chef Suzanne Vizethann...
Can I get a French toast
and a lox plate?
...bought this joint and started
making breakfast and lunch
for her hometown.
She's doing
something magic.
They care a lot about the food
that they put out,
and you can taste it.
Chicken biscuit.
It's a true drop buttermilk
biscuit
just like my grandma make.
Has a little bit of sweet,
salty, and crunchy.
FIERI:
Biscuit time.
So, we're gonna start
with A.P. flour.
Sugar.
Baking powder.
Salt.
Mix the dry ingredients.
Add the butter.
We make our own buttermilk.
Okay.
We're ready.
-So, just tacky.
-Yeah. We're making,
like, a batter.
Okay. Are we just pinching them
off on the side like this?
Absolutely.
And how many of these
are you making a day?
We sell about
1,200 biscuits a week.
This is 12 of the 1,200.
I'm already gonna be asking
for time off.
-Okay. Oven?
-Oven.
350, about 30 minutes.
We brush them at the very end
with melted butter.
Okay.
What are we making next?
So, we're making
our red-pepper jelly,
-which is gonna go
with our chicken biscuits.
-Okay.
We're gonna start with
roasted red peppers, sugar...
Whoa!
Ho-ho!
Apple cider vinegar.
Then some butter.
And then we're gonna
bring this to a boil.
We slowly add in the pectin.
Let it cool?
Mm-hmm.
It's ready to go after that.
All right.
What are we making now?
Our sweet-tea brine
for our fried chicken.
It's gonna start off
with sugar. Salt.
And then we're gonna pour
some hot water in.
Stir that up a little bit.
Garlic.
Black pepper.
I like that.
-Lemons.
-Squeezing them?
-Just lightly.
-This brine goes for how long?
-Two days.
-Wow.
Bay leaves, parsley,
and iced tea.
Now we put our chicken
into the brine.
We only have
our chicken biscuit
on the weekends for brunch,
and on Wednesdays.
Otherwise you're chicken
out of luck.
-Yes.
-Okay.
And then what are we
gonna batter this in?
We're gonna use our day-old
pancake batter.
I dig it.
So, we dredge
in the pancake first,
then in a flour dredge.
Let that chicken
cook through.
-Low and slow.
-See, I like that.
-Gives the extra crust
on the outside.
-Mm-hmm.
-So, here's our biscuit
that we made earlier.
-Okay.
-The red-pepper jelly.
-Mm-hmm.
And this is our chicken.
Little bit of parsley
for garnish.
We serve it with
our homemade hash brown
and house pickles.
I like the little
hash brown puck.
Nothing wrong with that.
Oh, that's a good bite.
The biscuit's spot-on.
But, boy, the crunch
on that chicken.
-That batter...
-Mm-hmm.
Really tasty.
The little pickle makes it.
The jelly's beautiful.
I get a little
bright note of that tea.
Kind of comes through
a little bit on the chicken.
I love the energy.
I love the scratch-made.
I love the refined
simplicity.
Thank you.
The biscuit melts in your mouth.
It's just incredible.
You think it's gonna
be too much,
but by the time it's gone,
you wish you had another one.
FIERI: Which is what keeps folks
coming back for more,
like regular customer
all-pro running back
Jamal Lewis.
Jamal, you've been all over
the world playing football,
so you've eaten everywhere.
How does this stack up?
It took me all the way back
down to south Georgia
to Grandma's house.
And Grandma lives
on Buttermilk Road.
Grandma lives
on Buttermilk Road?
on Buttermilk Road.
You can't make that up.
You know that.
Fried-egg BLT.
Buttermilk Kitchen
ranks up there
as true Southern
hospitality.
The food is always
homey and delicious,
but still creative
and different.
-Lox plate.
-The lox plate is very fresh.
The salmon is buttery
and smooth.
-What are we making now?
-Our lox plate.
So, this is the cure
that we make,
and we're gonna put this
on top of our fish.
-What kind of fish?
-We use a salmon trout.
-Salmon trout?
-Yes.
-Okay.
-We're using shredded red beets,
sugar, salt.
And we're gonna mix them
together.
The salt's gonna pull out
some moisture.
What are the beets
gonna do?
The beets are just there
for color.
-Okay.
-So, this is our salmon trout.
We're just gonna fillet it.
Okay.
Let's see it.
Black pepper.
And then fresh dill.
And then here's the cure
we made.
We just put it right on top
of the fish.
So now we're gonna
wrap it up.
And then this just goes
straight into the walk-in.
-Got it.
-Four days.
What are we gonna
serve it with?
Capers, red onion,
local Georgia lettuce,
lemon oil on top.
Cream cheese.
And then we remove it
and slice the fish,
and that goes right
on the plate just like that,
with our Jerusalem bagel.
I will tell you,
right off the bat,
the color is outrageous.
It really looks dynamite.
Nice, light,
rich, flavorful.
I can get that
any time of the week?
Any time of the week.
-That's what I would have.
-Thank you.
Your lox plate.
The lox plate is the perfect
combination
of creamy, crunchy, tangy.
I love it.
The food is on point
every single time you come.
On point. That's my line.
She took...
-Oh, sorry. [Laughs]
-Takes my line.
I've tried just about everything
on the menu. It's all great.
Whatever they've got going on
back there really works.
I completely understand
why you won now.
This is what you do.
You really are in this,
doing this, in every single way.
Well, thank you.
I appreciate it.
Nice job, Chef.
Up next, in Fort Collins,
Colorado...
Okay, this is different.
...an eclectic eatery...
It's small plate, it's great
drinks, it's high energy.
...where the veggies crank up
the variety.
I've made a lot
of strange pizzas.
This might take the cake.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Fort Collins,
Colorado,
about 60 minutes from Denver,
and here at the home of
Colorado State University.
Now, I'm here to check out
a joint
that's got a lot of character.
Let's see.
This team of four worked
together in one restaurant,
then they took off to open
their own to it,
that they like to call
"your neighborhood eatery."
If you're looking for a good
time, this is your place.
This is Restaurant 415.
♪♪
Two pork chops up.
It's eclectic.
It's different.
It's vibrant.
It's fresh.
And the Gimme sandwich.
The food is phenomenal.
The drinks are great.
Black IPA.
A lot of it's organic.
A lot of it's grown around here.
Brussels sprouts.
And it's the people
that really
make this restaurant
so amazing.
FIERI: The four cats
behind this joint,
Andre Mouton
and his daughter Amelia,
along with
their former co-workers
Seth Baker and Sean Olander,
banded together to become
co-owners here in 2012.
-This looks like a made-for-TV
movie, all right?
-[ Laughter ]
She's the chef.
He's the gangster.
And he's the college boy.
And Dad pays for it all.
[ Laughter ]
The cast of characters
that work here
are always just thinking
outside the box.
Woodland pizza.
Their entire pizza list is just
full of creative options.
Americano del Sur.
Garbanzo beans on a pizza?
This is the first time I've ever
had pizza with tomatillos.
FIERI:
What are we gonna make?
The Americano del Sur.
We're starting
with our pizza dough.
-Fresh yeast.
-Little sugar for it to chew on.
Olive oil.
Okay, so, the yeast and
the sugar coming together.
Kosher salt.
Organic, local flour. Water.
So, we'll let this go for,
what, about 15 minutes?
10.
So, our dough is all ready.
-Now we take out
the Captain...Hook.
-Maybe.
So, I hear you're a pro
at weighing things out.
Oh, yeah.
Tell me what
we're going for.
-6.4.
-6.4?
That's an odd number.
Little bit -- way over.
Rah!
[ Laughs ]
Mm...6.4.
6.6.
-Not bad.
-[ Inhales deeply ]
You're hired.
Okay. So, now we're gonna
make this pie.
We're gonna start with olive oil
and fresh garlic.
-[ Whistles ]
-That's a lot.
-Raw tomatillos?
-Yeah.
Okay.
This is different.
Garbanzo beans,
chopped up.
I've made a lot
of strange pizzas.
-This might take the cake.
-[ Laughs ]
A little bit of cumin seed.
-Cheddar cheese.
-Okay.
Fresh jalapeños.
Was it a dare to make this?
[Laughing] No.
And in we go.
Eight minutes.
Yeah.
Fresh cilantro to finish it off,
and that'll be it.
♪♪
Never in a million years
would I have thought
of taking a tomatillo,
slicing it thin like that,
and letting it cook off
in eight minutes.
I love the bite
of the tomatillo.
The acidity, the freshness,
and it's still
a little bit of crunch.
Jalapeño's great.
The garlic's
not overwhelming.
The meatiness of the garbanzo.
I'm telling you,
that's a spot-on pizza.
The Americano del Sur.
Just the right amount of classic
pizza flavor with a twist.
Off the hook.
Off...the...hook.
This may be the only place
I've ever had a tomatillo.
-You a vegetarian?
-Yes, I am.
Did I just bust into, like,
the vegetarian beehive?
Probably, 'cause that's
one of the things
that people like about it.
FIERI: But there's a buzz
on the meat dishes, too.
The pork lollipop.
Cooked to absolute perfection.
I love their waffles
and chicken.
FIERI: Or how about a steak --
of the veggie variety?
I'm looking for a little
break from the meat.
Blackened-cauliflower steak
is absolutely delicious.
It's on polenta, served with
a roasted-red-pepper sauce.
It looks like a seared
piece of meat.
Now what are we making?
We're making a
roasted-red-pepper sauce
for the blackened cauliflower.
All right, so let's do it.
We have roasted red peppers
here.
Now our Roma tomatoes.
I've been through
a few splashes.
Olive oil.
Some salt.
Little Cayenne?
Yep.
Granulated garlic.
[ Whirring ]
And now,
last but not least?
Some roasted garlic.
[ Whirs ]
♪♪
Oh, that's nice.
There's a little sweetness
to it, little acidity.
Sauce is done.
Now on to cauliflower.
Yeah. We'll work on slicing
the cauliflower up.
This is the key.
You get a nice steak
that stays together.
There we go.
That's nice.
What do you mean,
I have cauliflower ear?
[ Chuckles ]
Butter makes
everything better.
We let it sit and get nice
and caramelized on one side.
Now we'll hit it
with the...?
Garlic powder.
Little bit of soy sauce.
And then just a little bit
of lemon juice.
Okay.
We have our creamy polenta
ready.
With a little butter
and Parm in there.
And then we top it
with our sautéed greens.
Caramelized onions.
And then our beautiful
steak, there.
And last but not least?
The roasted-red-pepper sauce.
And there you have it.
-Big seller?
-Yeah.
♪♪
Mmm.
Cauliflower is meaty.
It's got great texture.
You got the richness of the
roasted red bell peppers...
And then the greens.
You get a little bit of the
bitterness coming through.
This right here...
This is a high-end dinner.
-Yeah.
-That's a great dish.
Here's your
blackened-cauliflower steaks.
As close as you can get to
eating a steak
without actually eating
a steak.
It's delicious, and it tastes
like I'm having,
like, a warmed salad.
Pesto pizza.
They love this city.
They love food.
You just feel it
in the restaurant.
It's just always something new
and something fun.
It's small plate,
it's great drinks,
it's high energy,
it's good people,
it's come here two or three
times a week.
This really...
This is a movie.
I'm gonna sell this.
[ Laughter ]
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
-Who taught you
how to make pizza?
-Echo.
-Who taught you
how to make pizza?
-Echo.
-And his brother --
-[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]