I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hey.
...it's a Thanksgiving feast.
Tastes like holiday
right off the bat.
Where the bird is flying
front and center.
That's like someone shot off all
the fireworks at the same time.
Of course, we got
the fully loaded
traditional dinner...
Get the hand cart.
I'm ready to get to my car.
...alongside
some real ringers...
Shut the front door.
...like turkey pizza
in Detroit...
Look at that!
...a turkey-twin
in Albuquerque...
People like to have a turkey
to look that good.
...turkey tots in Milwaukee.
This is crunch-a-tastical.
And in Syracuse,
one funkalicious waffle.
That is just,
in so many ways, weird.
Whether it's smoked...
Teach me the rub,
oh, wise one.
...sandwiched...
Rocks the house.
...or stuffed...
Holy moly.
...get ready to gobble up
this holiday hero.
Dude, that has changed
Thanksgiving for me forever.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
When I think of Boston,
I think of the Tea Party.
I think of the Sox, of course,
and now a place
called Mike's City Diner.
Now, it's not
because the owner's
an immigrant living
the American dream
or because President Clinton's
eaten here.
It's because of the way
they're cranking out
an American favorite: turkey.
Here you go, folks.
All right, Jay.
Thank you, Jay.
Turkey's fantastic.
The food is just amazing.
Did you see this plate?
That, it should be
almost semi-illegal.
WOMAN: I remember
the first time I came in here.
I said, "Is that real,
or is that a prop?"
FIERI: Oh, it's real all right.
One of four home cooked turkeys
they're doing up
and serving up every day here.
The all-American meal...
Nice to meet you.
...from a guy
who's telling you
he's living
the all-American dream.
How old were you
when you came to the states?
8.
8 years old.
And you came from...
Lebanon.
Jay Hajj fell into the food biz
as a dishwasher in his teens
then worked his way up.
It's excellent.
He bought this place 12 years
ago, left the original name,
but got right to work
on his own menu...
Can I have
some more fries?
...filled with fresh,
homemade local favorites.
We got some
good turkey dinner today.
When he tried his hand at
turkey, it was an instant hit.
It kind of happened
by accident,
when I had no place to put
the turkeys but on the steamer,
on top of the steamer.
And because it was
an open kitchen, just it grew.
It just got out of control.
I was like, "Oh, my God.
He's got real turkeys
up there on the bone."
FIERI: And on the plate
and in huge sandwiches --
turkey salad, turkey meat loaf,
turkey everything.
All made fresh every day...
HAJJ: Here you go.
Grab them now.
...Jay's way.
So,
someone made that for you?
Yeah.
That's...
Dude, that's snazzy.
Where'd you get the idea?
I mean,
I've done the beer-can chicken.
Years ago, I found
the stand for the chicken --
exactly,
the beer-can chicken.
And I realized that it cooks
the chicken a little better
because it's cooking
from the inside and outside.
You twist the...
I like this little maneuver.
...wings around the back.
Put your wings
behind your back.
There we go.
And we're not
gonna season this?
No seasoning.
No seasoning on the skin?
Unless
you want to eat the skin,
I found that it doesn't give
any extra flavors to the meat.
But if you say so,
I will agree with you.
[ Laughs ]
No need -- Jay's gonna
be all over the seasoning thing
with his homemade gravy.
All right,
now, this is onion powder,
garlic, and white pepper.
That is for the stock.
A little bay leaf?
Yep.
Turkish or Californian?
That's Californian.
Californian.
So we're just gonna
make a standard rouge?
There we go.
Come to papa.
You whisk that so you don't make
yourself any dumplings.
That's right.
Oh, that's good.
That's got real big flavor.
The stuffing will, too.
Celery, carrots.
Just dump them in.
Dump them right in.
You don't have
to sauté them or anything?
No. No. No, no.
That's for fancy places.
White onion?
White onion.
Spanish onion.
Yep.
I didn't talk to it.
How'd you know it was Spanish?
Now the turkey.
Little chunks
between the stuffing.
White pepper, cumin,
seasoned salt,
and the poultry seasoning.
Whisk.
Whisk a little bit.
And now we let it simmer
for about 5, 10 minutes.
We don't want
to break the veggies down.
That's right.
Put it right in here.
Wow.
And now,
I'm gonna smash-a-matic.
Now we got to bake this.
It's not done. There we go.
And there are potatoes to mash
and squash to whip up.
Whipping it where the whip
keeps it a little stringy.
You want it
a little stringy.
Everything you do has got
a little magic behind it.
But the real magic...
Here we go.
...is when
it's all on one plate.
Wow. The turkey
is super-money-tender.
The gravy, which is money.
Stuffing, you can still taste
the texture of the vegetables,
but it's creamy.
That's really good.
Have you eaten
the Thanksgiving-a-thon
here before, or...?
Thanksgiving in July.
Yeah, Thanksgiving
in September or February.
About
any time you want it.
Well, that's one of
the cool things.
You can get it
any time you want.
And if Thanksgiving on a plate
isn't your thing...
Those are our
pilgrim sandwiches, you guys.
MAN: That's my
Thanksgiving dinner.
That's right.
It is Thanksgiving.
Thank you very much.
All in a roll.
We're gonna make
a pilgrim sandwich.
Okay, so cranberries,
Put stuffing in it.
That's a nice giddy-up.
Usually, it's all white meat
unless the customer asks for...
So you pretty much make and do
and give whatever they want.
They want.
Holy enchilada!
How much you gonna give them?
You should call that sandwich
"The Goodnight."
How many of these
you sell a day?
About 45, I would say.
45 a day?
45, 50. Yeah.
No wonder you go through
700,000 turkeys a year.
Now, do you eat this with --
Is there, like, a contraption?
Well,
when there's gravy in it,
it's best to eat it
with a fork and knife.
I got the gravy, the stuffing.
That's awesome.
Thanks.
That stands up there,
the best turkey sandwiches
I've ever had.
Wow.
FIERI: Did you hear a piggy
noise when you bit into it?
[ Oinks ]
Say "Eat them up!"
GIRL: Eat them up.
I like it all mixed up,
just like Thanksgiving.
Put it all together.
MAN: Is this for real?
Well, let me get another guy
to help me eat it.
It's like that with everything
on the menu here --
huge portions
of real deal cooking...
Eggs Benedict...
Yes.
...with a huge chunk
of ham.
...that has folks lining up.
FIERI: Do you eat it all?
I make a good dent.
Yeah.
There's no gut down there.
Dynamic Duo,
and I get eggs and sausage.
FIERI: This is called
the Dynamic Duo?
Uh-huh.
They usually order them
before I sit down, so...
Oh, you're that loyal?
Yeah.
Gretchen. Amanda.
FIERI: For Jay...
And how's your breakfast
this morning?
FIERI: ...It's all about owning
a place people want to come to.
HAJJ:
I'm very proud of that.
...and locals want to
keep coming back to.
Everything's good?
Very good.
And a big part of that
is basic American home-cooking.
Like those four turkeys a day,
Thanksgiving anytime you want.
Really, I mean,
that's a serving.
Get another plate.
See, this is what I love.
This is the best thing
about this.
Dude, you are
the American dream.
I am.
I feel sometime, like,
it's like winning a lottery.
It is!
Get the hand cart.
I'm ready to get to my car.
In Sarasota, Florida...
Learn me.
...it's a chicken.
Rawr!
...it's a duck.
Whoa!
It's a...
Turducken.
...Turducken.
This is kind of like culinary
Disneyland for a dude like me.
When you're thinking
about turkey,
you're probably not thinking
of a joint like this.
The Alpine Steakhouse
in Sarasota, Florida
is more of a like a sirloin
and sausage kind of place.
But wait till you see
what they're doing with turkey.
It's gonna blow you away.
I love it.
All different flavors.
You can't get
anything better.
It's like Thanksgiving,
just, all the time.
No. Seriously, man.
They take a chicken,
they shove it in a duck,
and they shove the duck
inside the turkey.
And then they put a bunch
of stuffing and stuff on it.
It's absolutely fabulous.
FIERI:
It's called a turducken.
Just one of the hand-made,
homemade specialties
transplanted New Yorker,
Mark Rebhan,
and his son, Matt,
are cranking out...
Need some fries down.
...at the restaurant
and butcher shop
first opened by Mark's dad
32 years ago.
My dad basically came to Florida
to retire.
And that didn't last
too long.
Yeah, looks like
he really did a good job of it.
And went back
into business.
And I came down in '75,
and here I am.
About 12 years ago,
Mark says he heard about
something called a turducken.
Your dad comes home one day
and says,
"Guess what? You're gonna
start boning chickens,
ducks and turkeys,
making all the stuffing,
and shoving it together,
and then sewing it up
like a football."
What'd you say?
Well, basically,
he put one on the counter
and he started
doing one himself.
And we just did it
side-by-side.
Did you guys
learn it together?
Yeah.
Let me learn.
Learn me.
Well, basically, I mean,
you have a chicken,
a duck, and a turkey.
So what I'm gonna do...
Show me.
Is I'm gonna
take this chicken
and cut it
right down the back.
I call this
the scissor cut here.
You want to get
your knife tip in here.
This is the oyster meat
of the chicken.
Best part.
All right. Now, the duck.
Same way.
I like this.
All right.
This is kind of like culinary
Disneyland for a dude like me.
All right.
Big turkey.
If I'm down far enough,
this is gonna pull right out.
Oh.
Stock pot.
That was money, dude.
Yeah.
Okay. Can I try this one?
Sure. Absolutely.
Be my guest.
I feel a good
finger cutting coming in.
And you're just gonna kind of
go down, pull the meat.
There it is.
Good job.
Rawr!
We're gonna take the duck
and the chicken,
and I'm gonna hit it
with a little Cajun seasoning.
Throw the duck down.
Same with the chicken.
The chicken goes on
a little --
This is
the super-hot side.
A little less hot.
Right. Right.
Now what I'm gonna do
is put some of them
blackening seasonings
on there.
Whoa!
I like how you let me
jump in on this part.
Hey. You can cough.
FIERI: Now, to start
piecing this bad boy together.
Virgin olive oil here.
Get it into the seams,
the pockets where you took
the thigh bones out.
A little blackening
on this guy.
Then take some of this
cornbread stuffing here.
Now you're gonna go to your
spinach stuffing here,
and you're gonna put
some andouille sausage.
FIERI: And you guys make
the andouille sausage, also?
Here on premises.
Some
roasted red bell peppers.
Ah, that looks good.
Now you're gonna take your duck
inside this turkey.
Let me ask you this, boss.
Why isn't the chicken down?
He's bigger.
Well, turducken.
That's the turkey,
then the duck...
Give me the knife.
...then the chicken.
You're not doing
as much now.
You're just kind of hiding
it in there now.
Yeah. Now we're gonna
go to the chicken.
I bet you have
a lot of friends
come Thanksgiving
and Christmas time.
You're just gonna take it,
and you're gonna bring it up
and turn it like this.
Sometimes, it's best to have
a friend help you hold it.
Let me see
if I can find somebody.
When is your
spring clothing line coming out?
'Cause you're really
doing a MAC job.
Dude, you make that look
so easy.
That might be one of
the best-looking
uncooked food items
I've ever...
I mean, it's just beautiful.
And you just want to kind of
set it up in here.
Now, how long
does super bird take?
This super bird here
is gonna take about
12 to 13 hours
at 200 degrees.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
How many?
12 to 13 hours.
Okay.
So that goes in.
Slide it on in there.
So you just close
that oven and...
[ Whistles ]
It's hot.
One, two, three.
All right.
I feel better.
You do?
I'm gonna cut it
right down the middle.
The steam coming off that.
Aw, you should smell that!
Holy moly.
How's that look for you?
Ah, man.
It's a good combination.
Definitely the richness
of the duck.
And the fat.
And then,
you know what I pick up
in there is the andouille.
Mm-hmm.
And the chicken
has such a lighter texture
than the turkey.
Yeah.
That is a flavor-fest
right there.
Mmm.
Guy, you haven't even had
gravy on it yet.
Why would you cover that
with anything?
Seriously.
That's like someone
shot off all the fireworks
at the same time.
So good.
It's very,
very tender and moist.
FIERI: Seems Mark and Matt
just have a way with
stuffing things full of flavor.
Look at this thing.
There you go.
First course or main meal.
Set these guys loose, and you
really are talking turkey.
That's really good, man.
Isn't that good?
This has
fulfilled a dream.
Good.
Coming up
in Albuquerque, New Mexico...
Wait for it!
...we're baking
a whole different kind of bird.
That's beautiful.
And in Syracuse, New York...
Welcome
to flavor town.
...or waffle town for
the craziest turkey dinner ever.
Oh, my gosh!
That is killer!
On the road to flavor town.
I say it all the time,
"If it's funky, I'll find it."
I'm here in Syracuse,
New York right by the campus --
This is called S.U. Hill --
To check out out a joint
that's funky.
"How funky," you ask?
So funky,
it's called Funk-n-Waffles.
♪ Wait, wait, wait ♪
[ Raps indistinctly ]
And this is, like,
adult version of waffles.
Falafel Waffle.
There's nothing like it.
KYLE: ♪ Wait, wait, wait ♪
♪♪
Who runs around with
a bunch of waffle irons?
MAN: These guys.
Syracuse grads,
Kyle Corea and Adam Gold.
We threw these crazy
house parties
when we were in college.
I'd be deejaying
with my buddy.
And my business partner,
Kyle,
would be slinging waffles
at the bar.
You got your beer.
You got your waffles.
Really?
Just handing them out.
FIERI: And in 2007,
they made it legit
and kept it underground
when they opened this joint
in the basement.
♪♪
Savory waffles
and breakfast waffles
and lunch waffles
and fried chicken and waffles.
And for the ultimate
comfort food,
the bird is the word.
Jive Turkey -- a Thanksgiving
dinner on top of a waffle.
All right, we're gonna
make the Jive Turkey.
And that starts out
with our stuffing batter,
some cubed up bread, celery.
A little caramelized onion.
I got our eggs and rosemary.
Kosher salt.
A little bit of chicken broth.
Fresh ground pepper.
Spin this thing around.
So this is gonna go
in a waffle maker?
That's right.
This guy's ready to go.
Load that up.
I've never seen this before.
All right.
That is just,
in so many ways, weird.
Weird can be cool.
And now that
the waffle's down,
we're gonna start preparing
everything else.
We got some turkey right here.
Got it.
This is probably one of
the weirdest waffles
I've ever seen.
But I am going to
steal this.
All righty.
This guy's ready to go.
Let's just trim him up
a little bit.
Look at this thing!
[ Sniffs ]
Ah.
Let's throw some of this turkey
on there.
Let's get some of
these mashed potatoes.
Mouth is firing up.
Oh, yeah.
Then let's get a little bit
of gravy on it.
We're gonna
throw some cranberry sauce.
This might be one of
the funkiest things
we've ever tried.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm!
Shut the front door!
Oh, my gosh!
That is killer!
This is righteous.
The stuffing, it's the crunch,
the texture.
Mashed potatoes are legit.
That is funking ridiculous.
Dude, that has changed
Thanksgiving for me forever.
I'm coming here
for Thanksgiving.
You're in.
Welcome to flavor town.
Appreciate it.
♪ Wait, wait, wait ♪
FIERI: It is probably
the most ridiculous
funking waffle I've ever had.
Out of this world.
Delicious.
You can't go wrong.
This may be, like,
the capital of flavor town.
[ Raps indistinctly ]
♪ Wait, wait ♪
♪♪
[ Turkeys gobbling ]
So, it's Thanksgiving time.
Now, on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives,"
I have traveled all over
this great country
meeting all types of folks
celebrating this holiday
their own way.
So here I am
in Albuquerque, New Mexico
where a father-and-son team
have been baking up New Mexican
specialties since 1972.
And wait till you see
the type of turkey they bake.
This is Golden Crown Panaderia.
♪♪
It's a fantastic,
family-oriented bakery.
We feel really lucky to have
them right around the corner.
MAN: Great food.
Great customer service.
Where you feel like family.
FIERI: And they definitely know
how to make a Guy feel welcome.
Chris and Pratt are the best.
FIERI: The father-and-son
powerhouse behind this joint.
It all began in '72
when military-man Pratt Morales
got after
what he really loved to do.
PRATT: I always wanted
to be a baker.
And everywhere in the world
that I traveled in the military,
I would wind up
at the local bakery.
And it took just
another 30 years to get
a reliable business partner.
Couldn't afford a C.E.O.,
so I raised my own.
Together, they've turned out
a one-of-a-kind menu.
It's all about
the bizcochitos here.
I like the pumpkin empanadas.
FIERI: But when it comes to
Thanksgiving...
Isn't that beautiful?
...it's no surprise that
the bird is absolutely the word.
Turkey bread is great.
They make it look
just like a turkey.
Okay, what are
we gonna make?
I want to make some dough.
And this is gonna be the wheat
part of the turkey...
The wheat part.
...which is the leg,
the drumsticks, and the wings.
Got some nice
stone-ground wheat flour.
This is the bread flour.
A lot of gluten in here.
Put a little bit of salt
in there.
A little bit of shortening.
And let it mix
for a little bit.
Some molasses. That's gonna
give us some of the color.
It's also some
of the sweetener, too.
And to soften up the dough
a little bit,
we're gonna put
some honey.
Darling.
Beautiful.
And now we're going to add
some water to it.
I'm gonna add it slowly,
little by little by little.
Time for the yeast.
We got all the mixes in there,
so here we go.
We stop it,
bring it all out here.
And what I'm gonna do now
to make a turkey --
It's gonna be made
in three parts.
I'm gonna cut
the drumsticks.
The wings is gonna be
about 1/2 a pound.
There you go.
I have another dough
that I need
to make the white
part of the turkey,
which is the breast.
White flour,
a little bit of sugar,
salt, the shortening.
Gotcha.
Water.
And add the yeast.
Well, here we go.
Okay.
How long
have you been doing this?
About 40 years.
40 years
you've been making these?
Yes. Mm-hmm.
Oh, this is gonna be
the drumsticks.
I see it.
They're dark meat.
And then we're gonna do
the body,
which is the white part
of the turkey -- the breast.
And this is gonna go
right in here.
Seriously?
Okay. And I'm gonna twist it
like this.
Now we're gonna do
the wings.
Now we're gonna cut
the top part of the turkey,
separate it.
There you go.
And then the wings.
Separate them over here, also.
The bone.
Could have been
a taxidermist.
Giving it
a little texture.
There you go.
And I'm gonna do
a very light egg wash --
Give it the golden color.
Some rosemary.
A little bit of parsley.
Let it rise
as high as it will.
Wait for it!
Ready?
[ Drumroll ]
Ta-da!
Here we go, guys.
Look at that.
That's beautiful.
Isn't that beautiful?
I think people would
like to have a turkey
that looked that good.
I'm gonna slice you a piece.
How is that?
I'd like to have
some of the knee.
A little knee
right there.
Mmm.
Great crust on there.
I get a little bit
of that molasses.
There you go.
Try some of the breast.
There's a good part
right there.
It has huge crust on it,
but then it's just pillowy soft
on the inside.
I get a little bit
of that rosemary on that --
On that bread.
It tastes like holiday
right off the bat.
MAN:
It looks good on your table
with your flowers
or whatever you're doing.
MAN #2:
It's a great place to come
and feel like you're welcome
all the time.
There you go.
Pratt, amazing.
Thank you, my friend.
I love it.
FIERI:
Up next, on this full hour --
ultimate turkey fest...
That's good bird, man.
...in New Orleans.
This is like food Mardi Gras
right here.
There you go.
Thanksgiving, Big Easy-style...
I'm not kidding you.
That is ridiculously fantastic.
...all the way down to dessert.
How do you think
I should get after it?
So, I'm here in New Orleans,
on Elysian Fields Avenue,
right between I-10 and I-610.
Now, when I'm thinking
of great food in this area,
and there's a lot of it,
I got to be honest.
I'm not thinking about
Thanksgiving.
Well, that's until I heard about
Sammy's Food Service and Deli.
Turkey dinner,
working coming up.
It's just a wonderful
New Orleans local restaurant.
Turkey dinner.
FIERI: Doing a killer
New Orleans Thanksgiving.
Mmm.
Thanksgiving is a big time
in New Orleans.
Coming up.
And it's a huge tradition
for self-taught chef,
Sammy Schlegel...
When you cook everything
homemade...
...at a joint that used to be
his uncle's butcher shop...
Turkey dinner for here.
...till Sammy and his wife,
Gina, took over.
Turkey and oyster dressing.
Butcher chop
turns into a sandwich shop.
Now turns into making
some Thanksgivings...
Wonderful turkey
and cranberry. Mmm.
FIERI: Done the Big Easy way.
Dressing with oysters.
This is New Orleans.
We always have oysters.
That's the way it is.
Okay, well,
give me the rub down.
Get our beds set up
for our turkey to lie on.
Celery, garlic,
coarsely chopped onions.
These are also gonna
create a lot of great flavor
for our gravy later.
Absolutely.
Okay.
Paint him up.
A little garlic butter oil.
And that's gonna
give him a nice sheen,
make this poultry
seasoning stick to him.
Try not to miss any spots.
I think you might have
missed there.
There you go. Good job.
Now we're good.
Did you make
the chicken stock?
From the chicken backs.
It's a sandwich shop.
Put it in there.
So that's gonna make some
great gravy on the bottom.
Stuffing time.
Half a pound of butter.
We're gonna make
a bechamel sauce.
Bechamel?
For stuffing?
Some flour.
Build a little rue.
Throw a little
milk in there.
Get a nice, little,
creamy paste here.
Sauté some celery
and red bell peppers,
onions, green bell pepper.
I'm gonna need a spoon.
Well, listen,
I just showed up with car keys.
Ah, I'm telling you.
How you like them apples?
Please don't ask
for a mixer.
Put our butter in.
Sweat the veggies
a little bit.
Butter's kind of helping
them mellow out.
Take our oysters, put them
in this little chopping machina.
Break them up
a little bit.
That's not something
you see every day.
Releases up the flavor.
Huge.
Add some of this garlic here,
the thyme.
What was that word?
Thyme.
Red pepper flakes, black pepper,
some Cajun season,
bay leaves, chicken base.
Smells great.
Look at the amount of oysters
to the amount of bread.
This guy is crazy.
Hey.
You have the french bread
brought in.
Yep.
That's good, even stale.
All right, Guy.
I know this is the part
you've been waiting for.
Put the bechamel
in here now.
You're building the gravy
right into the stuffing.
Here we go with the oysters.
All that in.
I want that over some pasta.
Forget putting it in stuffing.
Grated Parmesan,
touch of lemon juice,
flat-leaf parsley.
Can I just start
dipping the bread in it,
forget the whole
Thanksgiving thing?
Sure. Absolutely.
Is that your five bucks
on the floor over there?
Oh, man. My lucky day.
Look at this.
So worth five bucks.
This has just got to be a dip
with some bread and some...
That's a thought.
Exactly.
Oh, and the oysters
are fresh?
Oysters are fresh.
And we have five eggs
beaten here.
Oh. Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Before you put the eggs
in it, man.
Now, I'm gonna fold this in.
I'm not kidding you.
That is ridiculously fantastic.
Gonna bake a little bit?
We're pre-cooking this.
We let those eggs cook.
Out of the oven,
into that bird.
Stuffing the bird.
Tuck his legs in.
Give him a little truss.
Birds gonna go in, 350.
Hour and a half?
Correct.
Now it's time
to make our gravy.
'Cause you already fortified it
with some chicken stock.
Turn this boat motor loose.
Add a little texture to it.
Here we go.
Go ahead and cut this
breast lobe off of here.
I don't really think it's fair
that I should have all that.
Feel free to share.
This seasoning
on the outside of this,
along with that garlic butter
rub you did,
that's good bird, man.
Put it on a plate here.
Did you make the cranberry?
Yeah, this is what you been
waiting for right here.
Right out of the bird.
And a little topping
of the gravy.
Mmm.
Dude, that's super-tasty.
Wow.
The turkey
is ridiculously tender.
The stuffing
has great texture to it.
I mean, it's big flavor.
You can really taste
the oysters, a boatload of them.
And the gravy is right on point,
up at ridiculous level.
This is like food Mardi Gras
right here.
There you go.
WOMAN: The turkey dinner,
it's really good.
The dressing is delicious.
You taste the oysters.
Oh, yeah.
Perfect
Thanksgiving meal.
And that's how you do
a Thanksgiving right
in New Orleans.
That's how you do it.
Mmm.
SAMMY: Pick up.
FIERI: And for dessert...
FIERI: Pumpkin bread pudding?
GINA: Pumpkin bread pudding.
Especially around Thanksgiving,
you got to have it.
You know when it starts off
with this,
makes me happy.
A mess of eggs.
Mess of eggs.
Whipping cream.
Get in there
and get you some.
Yeah.
Brown sugar, some white sugar,
roasted, pureed pumpkin.
And then we have some
pumpkin spice.
Necessary.
Some vanilla.
Vanilla.
Vanilla beans.
The scrapings
of the vanilla beans.
Yes.
Puree everything together.
A big pumpkin omelet
right there.
All right.
Now some French bread.
So, you take the french bread
that's left over,
grind it up, crust and all.
And we're just gonna
pour that right in.
Wow. You guys get serious
about this.
This will sit for,
maybe, 20 minutes
just to absorb
all the liquid.
Into the big chunks
of bread.
What are these little
tasty morsels?
Those
are candied walnuts.
Just to add a little bit
of flavor to it.
There's some nice,
little texture in there.
And then I'm gonna need
that pan right there.
There you go.
[ Whistles ] Down right
down to the number, huh?
Yeah.
We're gonna bake it at 300.
Down for an hour.
So you bring a lot
of that moisture out.
Just sits there
and compacts down.
That's crazy.
But I like
these little candied walnuts
that I just picked out of there.
Would you like a slice?
Is that cooled down
a little bit?
Them candied walnuts
taste like pumpkin pie.
I'm not a big bread pudding fan.
I got to be honest with you.
You aren't?
No.
It's the egg ratio.
Just not necessary.
Should be able to put
something else in it.
Chicken stock
would be good.
Oh, okay.
Well, we're gonna see
if you like this.
I'm a fan of
this bread company.
So I got to believe that with
the bread being chewy and all...
Oh, it's wonderful.
Rum sauce.
Cream, sugar, rum, cornstarch.
Ah.
How do you think
I should get after it?
Attack it from the left?
I'm gonna go
right in the center.
Look at that.
Smells like pumpkin pie.
[ Chuckles ] I'm gonna be
eating these words for a while.
That is some
tasty bread pudding.
It's got a good crunch.
It's not pumpkin madness.
The rum sauce isn't
super over-the-top sweet.
Could be the holidays
or what.
There's something
about that combo
because I just ate four more
bites than I expected I would.
That's really good.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Pumpkin bread pudding.
It's just fabulous.
MAN: Pumpkin-y,
nice cream sauce.
Oh, it's yummy.
Malata soup.
Anything that they put together
is excellent. Mmm.
And you can just count on coming
here and having good food.
Oh, yeah.
That's my brother
from another mother.
A little goatee,
some earrings,
bleached-out hair, I'll have
him working as my double.
You drive the '67 around.
I'll hang out
and make sandwiches.
Oh, you got a deal then.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up in Detroit...
All right, let me try to
explain things to you
as I shove my face with it.
...a joint putting the poultry
right on the pie.
[ Muffled ]
You got to try this.
And in Milwaukee, Wisconsin...
That gravy is legit.
...the whole shebang
rolled into a single bite.
Lucky you have her
keeping you in line.
She does.
This guy's out of control.
I'm here in Detroit, Michigan,
right across the street
from the Eastern Market,
to check out a pizza joint
where the owner
got his inspiration
from a little village that his
father grew up in in Italy.
He got so much
inspiration from it
that he named the joint
after it.
This is Supino Pizzeria.
Margherita going out.
Supino's is the best pizza
anywhere around here.
Large Supino coming out.
But not New York pizza,
Italian pizza.
What makes the pizza
so good?
MAN: The ingredients.
Everything's great.
Dave's excellent
at making pizzas.
MANCINI: Large verdure e funghi
coming out.
FIERI: That'd be Dave Mancini,
who chucked his own
medical career out the window
in 2008
to open his own pizza joint.
Where did you become
the dough aficionado?
Well, it was actually
Supino's,
the name of my father's hometown
in Italy.
And I went back there,
had some amazing pizza.
You were the tallest person
in the village.
By a long shot.
I was inspired by their pizza.
I thought it was amazing.
Over the years,
I developed a crust of my own.
In my little KitchenAid mixer
on my countertop.
I used to mix a batch of dough
almost every day
for about seven years straight,
just trying to get it
what I really wanted.
You ate pizza
seven years in a row?
My friends and relatives
benefited from it, as well.
All right.
So let's make some dough.
We're gonna start
by putting the dry mix
into
the 60-quart Hobart here.
What kind of flour
are we using?
We're using bread flour.
Nice elasticity.
So, now,
you're not a double-zero guy?
I'm not a double zero guy.
This is not Neapolitan.
It's more like
an East-Coast-American style.
It borrows a little bit
from the Italian styles, too.
A little bit of yeast
to go in this.
Dry active yeast.
Now I'm gonna make
my wet mix -- water, salt.
And the oil's gonna go in
the water here, too?
Yes, sir.
And we're just gonna
add this.
And when will you use it?
Tomorrow.
So you at least
give it a 24-hour rest?
Really develop some of
that yeast flavor.
But we'll use some of the dough
that you made yesterday.
Absolutely.
FIERI: Twice a week,
Dave hits the Eastern Market
across the street
for the freshest ingredients.
Thanks a lot, guys.
But the key topping for
one of his most popular pies...
Large City Wing Thing
going out.
...comes from
one of his buddies.
It's a smoked turkey.
Delicious.
Dave and the City Wing guy
collaborated on this.
Here's the City Wing Thing.
Now, are you really
a City Wings dude,
or did you just get the hat?
It's my spot.
Oh, that's your spot?
You're the dude?
Yes, sir.
Nice!
Nice, brine-smoked
turkey legs.
Yes, sir.
We're gonna make some
braised turkey legs
for the City Wing Thing
pizza.
Oh. See it every day.
Yeah.
I'm not a big fan
of chicken breast on pizza.
And I've been looking
for a poultry product.
Throw the smoked turkey legs
in here.
We got some
quartered red onions,
Frank's Red Hot Sauce.
Oh, so we are going after
a real chicken wing flavor.
A little bit of a tang.
Sugar.
Now we're gonna
cover this with water.
I've got garlic cloves,
really more for flavor.
So, how long we gonna
let it go for?
This is gonna go
for about 2 1/2 hours.
They're the bomb.
That's tasty.
The turkey leg and the thigh,
they have such rich flavor.
Yeah. We want
a little texture there.
We don't want
to turn it to mush.
Yeah, you don't want
to turn into mush.
But we want toothness
to the meat.
Toothness.
Toothy-ness.
Toothy-- tooth -- toothsome.
One of them words.
Yeah, yeah. Toothsome.
Just 220, 221,
whatever it takes.
[ Imitates light saber ]
This is really
where we're gonna separate
the men from the boys.
I like the method so far.
Building the edge.
[ Chuckles ]
That's it.
Cheese, and we're gonna
put sauce on top.
We're trying to keep
that crust nice and crispy,
so putting the sauce on top
keeps the texture.
And a little Gouda.
Smoked Gouda.
Fresh cubed mozzarella
over top of that.
The roasted garlic,
cherry peppers.
And we're gonna finish with
that turkey we braised earlier.
That's all she wrote.
That is all she wrote.
What temperature
you running that oven at?
This oven's going 670.
You got brick lining the top,
the bottom, the sides.
There's all kinds
of thermal mass in there.
This does not get cold.
I can open and close this oven
all day long.
Not something
you hear every day,
but today, on "Triple D,"
you've learned about
thermal mass.
FIERI:
With that kind of heat,
the pie bakes
for about six minutes,
with a spin midway
for an even cook on the crust.
♪♪
Look at that!
Enough of the Tom Foolery.
Set up and ready to eat.
Let me try to
explain things to you
as I shove my face
with it.
'Cause you can tell
I don't like it.
It's definitely
light and crispy.
Cross between, probably,
an American style
and a Neapolitan style.
Mmm.
I give you an "A"
in the dough, man.
A nice blend
between cheese and sauce,
a little bit of spice
from the vinegar
of the sweet peppers,
creaminess of the garlic.
[ Muffled ]
Oh, I love it.
MAN:
It's not Thanksgiving turkey
that someone
carved from the table.
It's smokey.
It's absolutely delicious.
And it pairs excellent with
those peppers that are on there.
MANCINI:
Large 'Pino ready to go out.
WOMAN: Dave is
an absolutely fearless chef
when it comes to making pizza.
I don't have a favorite.
I never order a pizza.
I always come in here
and say, "Dave, surprise me."
Do you think this is some of
the best pizza in town?
It's definitely
the best pies in town.
MANCINI:
We really want to make sure
it was something special.
It's set itself apart
a little bit.
You got to come down here
and try this pizza.
Well done, brother.
Really, well done.
You know, I think one of the tag
lines for "Triple D" should be,
"If it's funky, we'll find it."
Here we are on the east side
of Milwaukee.
Now, Lake Michigan's about
two blocks that way.
And the university's
about a mile that way.
And we're at a joint
that used to be a coffee shop
now turned into
a restaurant and a bar.
Welcome to the The Comet.
Bacon apple pie.
It's apple pie with bacon.
From pancakes and burgers,
to good old
American mac 'n' cheese.
It's all about the comfort food
Adam Lucks and his sister, Val,
have been cooking up
since they opened in '05.
Just you two winging it
and doing it your way?
Pretty much.
Essentially.
Ahi tuna.
FIERI: And they're putting
their mark all over this menu.
Chicken, peach jelly on top.
The vegan gyro.
Vegan Reuben tortilla.
Fantastic.
It's things you know
in kind of a different way.
FIERI: Like something
they named after a buddy,
A.J.'s Compact Turkey Dinner.
Mmm.
It's Thanksgiving and convenient
to eat ball form.
Killer stuffing,
mashed potatoes,
and fresh roasted
turkey breast.
Yeah. And you just
get in and mix it up.
We're gonna make them
into little balls.
And then we'll flour them,
beer-batter them.
How do you make
the beer batter?
Flour and beer
and salt and pepper.
Throw them
in the deep fryer.
They're get served
in a chicken gravy that we made.
Just place the turkey
right there
in the center of the gravy.
A little parsley for color.
And there you go.
Mmm.
That gravy is legit.
See, this is the component
that we're missing
in Thanksgiving, is crunch.
This is crunch-a-tastical.
Look at that.
Mmm.
The bacon haven
gravy emporium.
Get just about anything
off the menu,
and it's just really great.
Always tastes delicious.
Kimbo Burger, order up.
I think it's fantastic.
Lucky you have her
keeping you in line.
She does.
This guy's out of control.
Someone's got to boss
him around.
Bacon pusher.
[ Laughter ]
Up next, in Albuquerque...
My mouth is already starting
to water.
It smells so killer.
...sandwiches stacked
with a New-Mexican spin.
That's what she gave me.
Okay?
And a barbecue champ
in Glendale, Arizona...
Now I know why you been in
so many competitions,
why you won so many.
...smoking up
the centerpiece.
Aw, man.
But it sure is tender turkey.
♪♪
So, I'm here in the older part
of Albuquerque, New Mexico
known as North Valley.
Now, out here, you'll find
everything from horse ranches
to organic farms.
But more importantly, you've got
a cool, little restaurant
where the chef/owner started
by selling burritos
out of the back of her car.
Now she's got
a little take-out restaurant
where she's making, get this,
over 1,000 meals a day
for local schools.
This is Bocadillos.
How long on a T&A, sir?
It's real people
making real food
that real people want to eat.
YNIGUEZ:
After that, a Philly.
It's fresh. Love it.
They're good people, friendly.
Gonna be a busy day.
FIERI: And for owner and chef
Marie Yniguez, that's every day.
Since '09,
this Albuquerque native
has been delivering the goods
on what the locals crave.
We love chili in New Mexico.
We put it on everything.
FIERI: And they're a staple
of Bocadillos' sandwiches.
Not only does it taste good,
but it makes the whole
neighborhood smell good.
FIERI: So, I'm gonna follow
my nose down the road,
where Marie's cousin Charlie is
rockin' his Hatch-chili stand.
FIERI: So, let me
get this straight.
This right here is
the Hatch chili?
Yes, it comes from Hatch,
absolutely.
So Hatch is a place?
Yes, chili capital
of the world.
Let's turn her on.
Now, that's my kind of machine.
Only takes eight minutes
to roast these babies
to perfection.
My mouth is already starting
to water.
It smells so killer.
I've never seen
a chili-roasting stand.
Welcome to New Mexico.
Yeah,
welcome to New Mexico.
There we are.
Look at that!
And we're gonna cook with this?
Yes, sir.
In fact,
they're the crowning glory
on one of Marie's top sellers...
T&A on wheat.
FIERI: ...a New Mexican spin
on the turkey sandwich.
It's extremely flavorful.
It's legit.
We're gonna start
with the dry rub
for the turkey
for the T&A sandwich.
The T&A?
T&A.
What does T&A
stand for?
Turkey and avocado.
We got crushed peppers,
garlic, salt, pepper,
a little bit
of brown sugar.
Mix all this up
together.
Dry rub goes on?
Dry rub goes on.
Not on the inside?
No, I like it
to fall apart
as soon as I pull it
out of the oven.
And what is
this concoction?
So, that right there is
our house-made honey mustard.
Just go ahead
and toss it on.
Good to go.
Pretty.
Wrap it up in foil,
stick it in the oven
for 12 hours at 250.
All right,
roasted turkey.
Pretty much when you take it
out of the oven,
it just falls apart.
That honey mustard...
rocks the house.
It's pretty sick, huh?
We're gonna make
the green-chili apple chutney.
So, this is typical
chili peeling in New Mexico.
But you're wearing gloves?
Oh, yeah.
Because...
'Cause you don't know
if you're gonna touch your face
or anything else later.
Ready to go.
And then, basically,
you just...
Nice roasted flavor,
not super spicy,
but those will all range
in heat, right?
Yes.
And this chili apple chutney's
gonna go on the turkey?
Yes.
You get your diced apples.
A little bit of sugar.
So, about a cup and a half
of chilies.
Let it all
just cook down.
And then you'll start getting
the sweet and the hot,
and you'll be ready
to go.
So, we're gonna put it
in a hoagie roll.
Whole wheat?!
Yep.
You have a little healthy
somewhere in there.
[ Laughs ]
So, you put your green-chili
apple chutney,
let it soak into the turkey,
and that's kind of what makes
your whole sandwich.
Got the Muenster cheese
going.
As in Herman?
As in.
So, we got the green-chili
chutney going.
Here we go.
Is that a serious portion
or what?
That's a serious portion.
We do about 8 ounces
per sandwich.
Heirloom tomatoes fresh
from one of the gardens
here in the valley,
avocado.
There you go --
your very own T&A.
That's what she gave me,
okay?
That's a sandwich.
No, that's a dinner
for six.
What do you think, yeah?
The sweet and the heat
with the roasted turkey
and the mustard --
I don't know
where you came up with the idea.
It's delicious,
and the little burn
of the chili in the back...
It's just the love.
It is the love.
Carley,
you have a T&A sandwich ready.
The turkey's moist.
The bread is awesome.
It has all the chilies in it,
which is really good.
It's enough for two people.
That's for sure.
FIERI:
Marie just wants to feed you,
a skill she's taken
way beyond this tiny restaurant.
What are you doing
for all these hours?
I mean,
there are seven tables.
Well, because we feed
charter schools.
So I feed a thousand kids
before 10:00 in the morning.
A thousand?!
A thousand.
I'm here for my community.
I'm here for New Mexico.
I'm here to feed the future,
and we do it all from scratch
just the way my mom and my
grandma taught me how to do it.
You're gonna get good quality
every time you come.
Every time I come here,
I get something different.
I love this place.
You're priceless, girl.
I'm gonna tell you something.
You really are priceless.
You -- You give a lot
to people,
and it comes out
in your food.
You're the bomb.
Thank you.
Something's
a little strange here.
Joint looks like a diner.
But it's in Glendale, Arizona.
Oh, yeah, and they're serving
southern style barbecue.
You know, low-and-slow.
But they tell me the guy's
a competitive barbecue champion
who's won some of the biggest
competitions in the country.
Let's see,
I've got 300 awards.
What's the most prestigious
event you won in?
Oh, always Jack Daniels.
And it's those same recipes
that he's cranking out
for the neighborhood crowd...
Got the pork and slaw.
...every day.
MAN: The ribs are really good.
Great flavor,
and they're very tender.
The beef brisket. It tastes
really good, and it's moist.
I love the pulled pork.
The best.
FIERI: All done low-and-slow in
Roger's mesquite-fired smoker.
This is
the heart of the business.
He learned how to do this
almost 30 years ago
at a joint called Thee Pitts.
We got the whole farm on here,
or what?
What he opened
a place of his own,
he called it Thee Pitts Again.
I love the ribs.
I like the chicken wings.
I like the onion rings.
Sir, let's make it easy.
Anything you don't like?
No.
And beyond the smoke,
there's the rub.
Teach me the rub,
oh, wise one.
WAGNER: Season salt,
Spanish paprika.
It's got a little different
taste than regular paprika.
I toss in a little sugar.
A little sugar.
A little granulated garlic,
just a little bit of cumin.
And also a pinch of salt.
A little onion.
Some paprika.
The parsley.
Parsley.
Because if your paprika
is looking like that,
that's why I'm not winning
big competitions.
I've been thinking
it's parsley the whole time.
And then we have my ingredient
here that I add.
You've got about
half of one,
and then half
of your secret, so...
Yeah.
Now you're calculating it.
Who gets
to make the rub here?
I do.
Only you?
Yeah.
You're the only one
that makes the rub?
I'm the only one
that makes the rub
And that goes on everything?
Everything.
I've used this
in competitions.
And I've won chicken.
I've won ribs.
I've won shoulders.
It's very versatile.
He's even smoking whole turkeys
with it.
I've never had barbecued turkey.
This is a first.
So how do you serve this?
We pull it.
All pulled bird?
All pulled.
Give me the rundown here.
This is margarine
to give it a glaze.
It also let's the seasoning
adhere to it.
Give it the old rub.
Take this beauty
and just lay her right in.
FIERI: Now, how long
is that gonna run for?
Usually, a bird this size
will take about 14 hours.
Look at that.
Mmm.
Aw, man.
It sure is tender turkey.
Oh, yeah.
Were you talking to me?
Really, really good,
moist turkey.
Very tender.
FIERI: And great
with Roger's homemade sauce.
Sauce is money.
I start off with brown sugar,
Worcestershire sauce,
put in the mustard.
I've never seen that much
mustard go in a sauce.
Oh, yeah.
Want me to help?
Yeah.
That'd be great.
Heinz ketchup is what I use.
So, no cooking it.
No cooking it.
No messing with it?
No messing with it.
That's good sauce.
And folks here say
it's great on everything.
Tangy, but not too much.
He just, somehow or another,
just has the magic about him.
I think he just eats it,
sleeps it, and dreams it.
Well done.
Now I know why you've been
in so many competitions,
why you won so many.
Real deal.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on
"Diners, Drive-ins and Dives."
You're gonna start
hearing some funny sounds.
[ Wheezing ]
What is going on
right now?
'Cause it's still urgling.
"Urgling" is the term?
It's urgling?
I clearly should just write,
like, a new dictionary
for this restaurant.
You should have
the funking dictionary.