Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That's gangster.
...folks are partnering up...
Is this a huddle?
...making real-deal names
for their kitchen.
Nothing wrong with that.
In Falmouth, Massachusetts...
Oh.
...a two-couple team...
Outrageous.
...putting out
the perfect pickle.
Squishy mushy pickle.
Nobody likes
a mushy pickle.
Then just north of town...
Little cottage
tucked away in the woods.
...a husband and wife duo
keeping it legit...
I'll have nine bowls
of this.
...and all in the family.
I see why everybody
loves you guys.
And in Fort Collins,
Colorado...
Brother,
I'm telling you.
...a "Triple D" alum
plus an NFL star...
Shoulders back, bellybutton in,
flex the core,
and get into this.
FIERI: ...score big on
a wild and woodsy flavor zone.
Make that happen.
Look at that.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I got a question for you.
How do you get Guy Fieri to roll
into Fort Collins, Colorado,
located right between Cheyenne,
Wyoming, and Denver?
Well, I'll tell you how.
You get Aaron May from
Over Easy Cafe in Arizona
and powerhouse NFL player
Jared Allen to come together
and open a place.
This is The Lodge
Sasquatch Kitchen.
I come to this place
because it's a little unusual.
The food is fantastic.
Large meatloaf.
Fit for a lumberjack.
I think that there's a very good
chef that works back there.
FIERI: There is. "Triple D" alum
and my buddy Aaron May.
Remember Aaron,
we shot Over Easy,
and this was years
and years ago,
and this guy has built
a restaurant empire.
Which includes joining forces
with all-pro Chicago Bears
linebacker Jared Allen
to open a mountain-like lodge
in 2014.
It's the only place in town
like this.
The flavors are always
very unique.
I need pork chili
on the line.
It has really great
green chili flavor.
And the fact that it has,
like, the big chunks
of pork in there,
that's what
I'm talking about.
Green chili and pork stew.
One of my favorite things.
I know you love it.
Colorado has great produce,
great chilies,
great western tradition of this
high mountain food, right?
I want everybody at home
right now to tune in
to how many times today
Aaron May says "right."
Right?
[ Bell dings ]
[ Laughter ]
Right?
[ Bell dings ]
I'm just gonna be
the scoreboard in the back.
[ Laughs ]
So, I've got some beautiful
boneless pork butt.
And I'm just gonna
cube this up.
Nice big chunks, right?
Right?
[ Bell dings ]
[ Laughs ]
And we're gonna go ahead
and dredge this
in some seasoned flour.
What do we season it with?
Little bit
of black pepper,
cumin, chili powder,
onion powder,
some garlic powder.
Now you're gonna
dredge it.
I'm gonna dumb it down
for everybody.
Dredge just means
cover in flour.
Jared is gonna be translating
for everybody at home
who is having
any questions.
Right?
[ Bell dings ]
So, we're gonna brown
that up.
Got a nice amber ale here.
All the beer.
Start the braise
a little bit.
Next step?
I'm gonna add my vinegar
and some ground
cumin seed.
You got to romance
the pork, Guy.
Michael Douglas'
lesser known movie,
"Romancing the Pork."
♪♪
Now what's gonna happen?
I'm gonna make
a little puree.
Minced garlic,
chopped white onion.
I got some green chilies
that we roasted off.
Those are Anaheim chilies,
jalapeño chilies,
and chicken stock.
All that flavor.
Straight to Flavortown.
How long is this gonna cook?
About 45 minutes.
Also known as
the stewing process.
And before we serve this dish,
what do we got, Aaron?
We're gonna make another
green chili puree.
Roasted chilies,
seeded and stemmed.
And chicken flavored
chicken stock.
Comes from real chickens,
too.
Real chickens?
Yeah.
Stir that in,
make sure you get that
really smoothly
distributed.
Which would mean, Jared?
Stir evenly.
Another 15, 20 minutes.
Just kind of let all those
flavors come together.
Okay.
Here we go.
This is what
I'm really good at.
I'm like research
and development.
Green chili pork.
Top it with a little bit
of this jalapeño jack.
I've got some blistered
serrano chilies here.
Oh, that'll be nice.
All just dig right in.
This is --
is this a huddle?
Ready, break.
Cheers.
Jared, I'm gonna
default to you.
What are you tasting?
The texture of the pork
is just great.
It kind of falls apart
in your mouth.
Little creaminess
of the cheese, right,
as it's slowly melting 'cause
the temperature is just right.
You get just enough spice
to keep you right in there
and keep you diving in
for more.
Just raging flavors here.
I agree with everything
he said.
I'll tell you what
the kicker really is,
though,
is all the beer.
I just get that tone
right underneath it.
Darn good chili.
It's the real deal.
Don't mind me.
We don't have, like,
a cool restaurant
full of tables either.
It's all right.
We'll be right here.
Pork green chili.
How is it?
So good.
Very smoky, very thick.
It's got the right heat level,
big chunks of pork in there.
MAN:
There's always huge portions.
I think that's kind of
what they're going for,
the whole log cabin idea.
I love the vibe.
WOMAN: There's wood covering
just about every surface,
so it's got this
camp lodge feel.
It also combines
Colorado's three best things --
sports, outdoors,
and our food.
MAY:
LSK burger, rare.
The burgers are awesome.
I got the habanero burger
going right now.
I just thing the ingredients
are unique.
FIERI:
So, here's the deal --
Hanging out with
my good buddy Aaron May
and of course Jared Allen.
When we come back, we might
actually make another dish.
Or just talk the entire time
and make no sense.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back to
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
from beautiful Fort Collins
here at The Lodge
Sasquatch Kitchen
with my man Aaron May
and Guy.
That's all the license
is gonna say from now on.
Guy.
Just Guy.
First name and last name.
Guy Guy.
FIERI: And that's all-pro
NFL linebacker Jared Allen,
who owns this joint along
with Chef Aaron.
What are we making next?
Our habanero
Parmesan burger.
Habanero...
Habanero Parmesan.
Habanero Parmesan burger.
Melding cultures.
WOMAN: Habanero burger.
It's such a beast to behold.
It's got a nice bit of heat.
There's a nice dill sauce on it,
so it kind of balances it out.
We're gonna make
our dill dip
that we're gonna use
as a spread.
Dill's actually a spice,
Guy.
I didn't know
if you know that.
[ Both laugh ]
This is Jared's first run at
the culinary analyst position.
I'm gonna take
equal parts mayonnaise,
yogurt, sour cream.
Mix those up.
Dill, parsley,
shallots, garlic,
and I'm gonna give it
a good mix.
What's next?
We're gonna make our
habanero Parmesan patties.
Mmm.
This is 80/20
ground chuck.
I took a bunch
of these habaneros
and I minced them up
finely.
Mincing means small pieces.
What you do to quarterbacks.
Small pieces.
Yeah.
Try to mince them.
Yes.
I've got this bacon.
We cooked this bacon
and we chilled it.
Pretty big pieces
of bacon.
We're not going
for subtle notes.
No subtle notes.
This is a bacon slap
in the face.
And I've got shredded
Parmesan cheese.
Now I'm just gonna go ahead
and work this through.
You don't want to
over mix it.
We're not making meatballs,
we're not making meatloaf.
There you go. That's how
we make them for Jared.
This is Jared Allen burger.
Gonna go 8 ounces.
We're gonna make
a nice patty.
Get it on the grill.
♪♪
Let me get down
with the dill.
Little bit on the top
and the bottom.
And when I build
the burgers,
I like to put the lettuce
and tomato on the bottom.
Okay.
Habanero Parmesan burger
for you.
I like it.
We're gonna do
the Jared Allen double.
No lettuce,
but extra meat.
So, Jared,
you've seen the hunch.
Yep. Shoulders back.
There you go.
Bellybutton in, flex the core,
and get into this.
Just get right after that.
Make that happen.
Look at that.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Mmm. I love the heat
in the burger.
The bacon, you cooked it down
enough to where you get
the texture of the bacon,
you get the flavor of the bacon,
and then you get
this tender burger
which you've been able
to cook medium rare.
Brother, I'm telling you,
it's a simple dish,
but it has to be executed
the right way.
It's kind of like a play.
If you just do what
you're supposed to do
and commit to what
you're supposed to do,
you're gonna
make it happen.
You made it happen, man.
That's outrageous.
Thank you, man.
I love it.
Habanero Parmesan burger.
Probably the best burger
you've ever had, right?
One of them for sure.
It has some serious kick.
My mouth's still on fire.
The creamy dill sauce on the top
really cooled it down
and made it excellent.
Fried chicken and biscuits.
I love the lodge.
Come hungry. It's great.
Right?
[ Bell dings ]
♪♪
Aaron, I know that everybody
thinks you're just
another pretty face, but,
dude, you can really cook.
Nice job.
Thanks, buddy.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up,
in Falmouth, Massachusetts...
There you go.
Pile it right on.
...the bomb
breakfast-lunch café...
Oh, my gosh, dude.
...serving savory sandwiches
and one killer chip.
This right here
you could've dredged in sand --
I would eat it.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Falmouth, Massachusetts,
right between --
Let me get this right --
Plymouth and Hyannis,
in a small, little town that,
during the on-season, they've
got like 200,000 people here.
In the off-season,
it's more like 30,000.
Now I'm on the main drag to
check out a funky little joint
where two couples
are kind of in a pickle.
Well, not exactly --
This is the Pickle Jar Kitchen.
♪♪
Town Hall up.
Everything that they make here
is just original.
There is an energy about it
when you walk in.
FIERI: Maybe because
it's run by old friends...
Beet salad.
Thank you.
...Kevin and Elizabeth Lay
and Ben and Casey Gallant.
How did the couples meet?
We met in college --
Johnson & Wales.
All three of them
went to Johnson & Wales.
All three of you went
to Johnson & Wales?
FIERI:
And a couple of decades later,
this culinary-school grads
ended up opening this joint
together in 2013.
Road Race Roll.
It isn't like going, well,
to any other restaurant
we've been to.
One more pickle chip.
A place that's called
the Pickle Jar
ought to have fantastic pickle
chips, and they certainly do.
Highly addictive.
Let's get after this.
KEVIN: We're gonna start
with whole Kirby cucumbers.
We've got to nip the ends off,
the blossom ends,
ends to a crunchier
pickle, yeah.
Hence -- That makes
a crunchier pickle?
Yeah. So there's enzyme
in the blossom end.
Something about that
leads to a squishy...
Squishy mushy pickle.
Nobody likes
a mushy pickle!
Let's start the brine.
Water.
White distilled vinegar.
Salt.
And a little bit of sugar.
Let the salt dissolve.
Yeah.
Fresh dill.
So these will get loaded up.
Now we're gonna throw in
our whole juniper berry.
Dillseed.
Tellicherry peppercorns.
Yellow mustard seed.
Got it.
Whole coriander seed.
Coriander. Very nice.
Jalapeños with and without seeds
and some fresh garlic.
The brine is gonna get
poured over the top.
I like it.
Throw them in the cooler
for about three days.
♪♪
Let's eat some pickles.
That is crunchy like
a potato-chip crunchy.
Gonna dredge 'em up.
We got flour, cornstarch.
350?
Three to four minutes.
Nice golden-brown, crunchy,
served with a Tellicherry
peppercorn ranch dressing.
♪♪
Oh, my gosh, dude.
This right here,
you could've dredged in sand --
I would eat it.
It's thin, balanced favor,
perfectly seasoned.
And the crunch!
Oh.
I haven't even
done this yet.
Oh, yeah.
That gets ridiculous
right there.
Dude, that is gangster.
Thank you, sir.
Outrageous.
♪♪
WOMAN: I think they're like
potato chips.
You do not eat just one.
Absolutely a guilty pressure.
All right, and you get
The Firehouse.
[ Laughing ]
Thank you very much.
Enjoy.
Once you dine once here,
you're really hooked.
I have been twice here
twice a day, I'm proud to say.
FIERI: Which would mean
for breakfast and lunch,
because they're not
serving dinner
or other things you may expect.
We aren't like your typical
Cape Cod restaurant.
We don't serve fried clams.
Open Faced up.
This is incredible.
It is pulled pork
on a chai-flavored scone.
I actually think about it a lot.
[ Laughs ]
Barbecue in Cape Cod?
Just a braised pork butt.
We're gonna start with
our rub.
Got our house smoked
kosher salt.
I taste it.
Tellicherry peppercorns.
Summer savory.
Granulated garlic.
Smoked paprika.
Spanish paprika.
Sounding good to me.
New Mexican chili powder.
Ground cumin.
A little cayenne.
Chipotle powder.
Celery seed.
Okay.
Juniper berry.
Brown sugar.
And some ground
coriander seed.
So everything that you own
or have ever heard of.
Yeah.
I get some fresh garlic,
Spanish onion,
bottom of this pan here,
and I'm gonna rub
this pork down.
How long's it gonna go
in the oven?
First we let it
sit overnight.
Then we go to the oven --
350 degrees, 7 hours or so.
[ Whistles ]
Next up?
We're making our
cheddar scallion scones.
Say that five times fast.
Cheddar scallion scone,
cheddar scallion scone,
cheddar scallion scone.
The man.
So we're gonna take
heavy cream,
lightly mix in
some whole eggs.
Okay.
Put that on the side.
We're gonna take our
all-purpose flour,
baking powder, kosher salt,
shortening,
and butter.
Okay.
Gonna let this go
for a little bit here.
Throw in our cheddar cheese
and scallion.
Okay.
And then stir it around
just a little bit.
Once it's incorporated,
drizzle in our wets.
So you got yourself
a tacky little batter.
Yep.
Start working that dough
a little bit.
Not too much, just patting it
down into shape.
♪♪
Now we're gonna brush them
with a little egg wash.
And what temperature are
these gonna bake off at?
350 for about 25,
30 minutes.
Look at that.
Nothing wrong with that.
Looking at our
pulled pork here.
Let's toast up our
cheddar scallion scones.
Those look awesome.
And we go with
the braising liquid in the pan,
then a little Spanish onion,
jalapeño peppers, green peppers,
and poblano peppers.
We're gonna add some
of this pork here.
There you go.
Pile it right on.
Little drizzle of
the barbecue sauce.
Gloss it up.
Throw our scone
on the plate here.
Drop our five-chili
barbecue pork
and top it with
our smoky cheddar sauce.
Drizzle the barbecue.
And some house pickled
red onion.
There you have it.
♪♪
It's not just
a pulled pork sandwich.
It's got a lot going on
with the fresh baked scone.
You make the sauce.
A little bit
of the pickled onion.
The combo of the sofrito
and the cheese sauce
that put this
over the top.
That's sophisticated
right there man.
Open Faced is all set.
The scone and pulled pork
together -- incredible.
It's just perfect.
If people are
coming downtown,
the Pickle Jar
is the place to come.
It's different, it's refreshing,
it's creative,
and you guys treat it
with a lot of respect.
Well done, my brother.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
just outside of town...
Wow, that's nice.
...to an out-of-the-way
culinary oasis...
This is just the delicacy
of the area.
...that makes you feel
right at home.
Funky little hut, mom-and-pop
joint. It's just what I wanted.
♪♪
So, I'm here at Cape Cod,
in the town
of Falmouth, Massachusetts,
right over the Bourne Bridge.
Now, there are two types
of restaurants in this area.
You got those
that are seasonal
and those that are loved
by everybody.
You're right -- the ones
that are open year round
like this joint,
Dana's Kitchen.
Smoked scotch salmon up.
I love this place.
I really do.
We'll come in the morning
for the pastries
and then come back
at noon for lunch.
Can't stay away.
Goat cheese salad.
Dana and Art are just really
friendly people, really kind,
hardworking, and they
just make delicious food.
Let's get this out.
FIERI:
That's husband-and-wife team
Dana and Art Tillman,
who first met over food.
I grew up around here.
She grew up in Detroit.
We met at The Culinary Institute
of America.
Then, after getting married
and having kids, well,
they took another leap together
in 2005.
I dreamed a big dream
for my husband and I
to open a family business.
♪♪
You can feel the love
in the food.
Everything looks beautiful
when it's presented to you.
It's really fresh, and it's
really wonderful. I love it.
The soups here are the best.
I need a kale soup.
The Portuguese kale soup,
just full of all good stuff.
One of the heartiest soups
you can have.
FIERI: All right,
what are we making first?
We're gonna make
the chicken stock.
For the Portuguese kale soup?
Yes.
Okay.
Gonna put the chicken in.
Then we're gonna pour
the water in.
So a little mirepoix.
Carrots, celery,
and onions.
So we're gonna add
the garlic.
Okay.
Parsley?
Bay leaf.
How long are we gonna
let this --
Four to six hours.
And then we'll strain it,
and that's the beginning
of the soup?
Exactly.
Now we got some schmaltz.
You got some schmaltz.
We got us some schmaltz.
Straight-up chicken fat.
And the onion, chopped garlic,
little salt and pepper,
and then the sausage --
linguiça.
Whose linguiça?
A company up the street --
They're 100 years old.
I like linguiça.
We're adding the kale.
Gonna get it all
in there, huh?
We're gonna get it all in,
and it's gonna cook down.
Now we're gonna add
some hot chicken stock.
I'll have nine bowls
of this.
And then kidney beans.
Boiled russets,
peeled and chopped.
A little hot sauce.
A little hot sauce --
about seven shots.
Hey, look, squirrel!
Oh, yeah, where?
5, 12, 15, 18, 19, 20.
[ Chuckles ]
Dish up the kale soup.
What are we serving
this with?
Some oyster crackers.
Of course we are.
Mmm!
I love a good soup.
This is great soup.
And when you're making
your own chicken stock
using locally made linguiça
with kale, simple seasonings,
and you let it
slow cook...
Mmm! It's just what I wanted
when I pulled up --
little cottage
tucked away in the woods,
cold day, grabbed some
sausage and kale soup.
I see why everybody
loves you guys.
Aww.
Mmm!
Hot Portuguese kale soup.
It's excellent.
It's a lot of kale.
The sausage is wonderful.
It's not too spicy.
FIERI: Finding a little oasis
like this that's serving soup
and doing cookies and pastries
and all that...
It's the best.
It's a gem.
It is really a nice
Cape Cod restaurant.
WOMAN: We're kind of off
the beaten path,
but that's always
where the best food is.
It's truly the family
running the show.
Absolutely.
Spicy B.L.T.
They put so much time and effort
into the sandwiches.
They're so good.
Soft-shell crab.
The soft-shell crab
is amazing.
WOMAN: And you know you get
the whole crab,
so it's really just
kind of the experience.
FIERI: Okay.
We've got
soft-shell crabs.
These are live?
Yes, they're in
a dormant state,
and they've molted
their shells.
This is just the delicacy
of the area.
Yeah, really up and down
the East Coast seaboard.
That's a blue crab.
♪♪
Seasoned flour.
What's in
the seasoned flour?
I just use kosher salt
and coarse ground black pepper.
Egg.
Very hot sheet tray.
Roast them in the oven
what temp?
About 500 --
hot as possible.
And how long will they take
till they cook?
7 to 10.
And what does this
get served on.
On the homemade
challah bread.
[ Sniffs ] Mmm!
Wow, that's nice, huh?
Holy challah.
Now we're into
making the spread.
Yep.
Mayonnaise.
Garlic.
Little lemon juice.
Lemon juice.
Smoked paprika.
Cayenne pepper.
Mix this all together here.
Now we put it together.
Rouille.
Put some on there,
huh, boss?
Yeah.
Bacon, avocado.
Very California of you.
This is the Dana Club.
This is how she makes
her club sandwich.
Then the crab.
Tomato.
Little bit of lettuce.
And we're ready
to slice.
♪♪
That's it, babe.
All right,
let's get after it.
That's the stuff.
You can really
taste the crab.
They're full of meat.
They're beauties.
Got a little crunch to it,
seasoned appropriately,
local bacon,
make your own bread,
make your own
rouille sauce,
clean and cook your crab,
don't fry it.
I think that's one of the keys,
'cause I get the saltiness,
I get the fresh seawater
flavor to it.
If you're in this area
and you're known for
soft-shell crab,
that's how you do it.
Soft-shell crab.
MAN:
The soft-shell crabs,
you only get them
once in a while,
but there's nothing else
like it.
The crab is so soft and the
challah bread is my favorite.
I got a spinach salad.
I love the spice.
Always leave satisfied.
MAN:
It's just a great atmosphere
to come out here
and have a nice meal.
Funky little hut,
mom-and-pop joint,
serving the best that you have
to offer when it's season,
doing it the right way.
Thanks, buddy.
Well done, brother.
Appreciate it.
So, that's it
for this Flavortown road trip,
but don't you worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
We need a group hug
after that burger.
[ Laughs ]
Come on, guys.
Bring it in here.
The family atmosphere.
[ Laughter ]