Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I'm savoring every bite.
...we're dishing out
a heaping helping of home...
[ Muffled ] As you can see,
I'm really not enjoying it.
...brought right here
from all over the world.
Look at that.
This isn't my birthday.
In Denver, Colorado...
ALL: Opa!
FIERI:
...a little slice of Greece...
Where has that been
all my life?
...going big
on a real-deal feast...
Which way's the gym?
I got to find a treadmill.
...in Atlanta, Georgia...
Let's plate this up.
...a marriage made
in culinary heaven...
Girl, it is spot on.
...putting out
legit Southern specialties...
That's the bite
right there.
...And in Richfield,
Minnesota...
Off the hook!
...a full-blown
Mexican experience...
This right here [whistles]
up top.
...pushing the flavor jets
into overdrive.
If there was a county
in Flavortown named Tamale,
that would be it, man.
That is it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here
in Richfield, Minnesota,
about 10 minutes
from downtown Minneapolis.
Now, this is a great place
to come to.
One, a bunch of my Triple D crew
lives here.
Two, they have got
an eclectic mix of restaurants.
But I got to be honest with you,
when my crew tells me
they've got a real-deal
Mexican joint in Minnesota,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Andale.
♪♪
MAN: You can't get this kind
of authentic Mexican
anywhere in the Twin Cities.
RANGEL:
Sopa de mariscos.
It's like walking into
a little cafe in Mexico.
FIERI: And much more,
'cause when Fernando Mellado
and Jorge Rangel opened in 2011,
they went for,
well, pardon the expression,
the whole enchilada.
One side is
full-blown restaurant.
Right.
And then a huge menu.
The other side is market.
You got a butcher shop,
you have a bakery.
Right, right. We get
a lot of people coming in here
for the restaurant, then come in
and explore the market.
So, that's a big deal.
You can come have your meal,
and go right next door,
get some groceries, go home, and
try and recreate your own meal.
Three tacos pastor.
The al pastor tacos
are like getting street tacos.
They're super fresh
with a nice cilantro taste
and the crispy onions.
What are we into now?
We're gonna make the
al pastor sauce for the tacos.
Got it.
We're gonna start with
a guajillo pepper, orange juice,
lime juice, cumin, black pepper,
bay leaves, oregano.
Mexican oregano is nice, big,
super-bold flavor.
Achiote.
This is the annatto seed
that's made into a paste,
but there's also flavors
in this, okay.
Garlic, onions, salt,
white vinegar.
And then we use the big blender
right here.
Don't get this on me.
I only have
one spiritual gangster shirt.
Okay, so, we take
the sliced pork,
we put it in there,
and how long will it marinade?
For 24 hours.
Next up?
We're gonna do the salsa verde
right here.
We have
the boiled jalapeños,
garlic, the onions,
salt, avocados.
And use
the immersion blender.
Okay, then start pouring
the oil slow.
How's that?
That's fantastic.
Next thing we're gonna do
is make our tacos.
Onto the flat top,
little bit of oil.
Drop some onions.
And a little bit
of bacon.
of bacon, too.
And pineapple.
All gonna cook together.
We do, like,
a double tortilla.
How many do I get, 12?
Three.
Three works for me.
Okay, so we got
the al pastor taco.
Cilantro, onions.
A little lime juice.
Okay.
Here's the avocado salsa
that we made.
Let's see
what you think.
There is no way
we're in Minnesota.
No way.
The meat's
perfectly marinated.
It's got nice crisp to it.
Right amount of onion.
Tortillas are charred.
The salsa is outstanding.
Making me hungry.
I'm gonna
tell you what --
The way you cook,
the discipline.
Scratch-made -- I mean, they
scratch make just everything.
Outstanding, Chef.
Nice job, buddy.
Thank you.
Wow.
The pork had lots of flavor.
It's really tender and juicy.
Salsa verde had a lot of kick
to it from the jalapeños.
MAN: Everything
they make here is fresh.
I mean, they have
their own butcher here,
they process their own meat.
Are you always bringing in
the whole animal?
Yeah, we do.
They don't cut the meat
the same way in Mexico
that we cut it
in the United States.
Yeah, we do
a totally different cut.
Majority of everything is gonna
be cut real thin.
That's correct, yeah.
There you go. There's
your Mexican butchery 101.
That's all I know,
by the way.
Torta ranchera.
MAN: Well, there's obviously
some very knowledgeable people
who prepare this food
because it's done very well.
Carnitas tamales.
The tamales are awesome.
They're very soft,
but with a bold flavor.
And we're still gonna
make tamales?
When we come back,
we're hanging out at Andale
in Minnesota of all places
having some bomb Mexican food.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're hanging out
here in Richfield, Minnesota.
I got to
tell you something --
I've been to some taquerias
around the country,
but my crew from
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
said this is the place
you got to check out.
We'll get off the plane
in Minneapolis
and head straight here
because it's
the taste of home for us.
It's just like
the tacos we had
when we were all
down in Mexico together.
The al pastor, off the hook,
and now we're making?
The carnitas.
We're making carnitas
for tamales,
and the hood's on because
this is smoking, this is hot,
and you got to have this
cauldron to make this happen.
We're gonna start
with searing the meat.
And what kind of fat
are we using?
Lard.
We're using lard.
So, now we
seared it all off.
Cola.
You got to do
a little cola.
You know why? Color.
Cinnamon.
I've made
a lot of carnitas.
I've never put cinnamon in it.
I like this one.
Oranges.
And salt.
We're gonna put
the pork stomachs in there.
Boy, I hope they're not
out of pork stomach today
when I go to Andale.
[ Chuckles ]
We're gonna cover
with the pork skin.
More lard?
Yeah.
This is awesome.
A hot tub of pig.
Okay.
And we're gonna let it cook
for six hours.
How often do you make
this much carnitas?
We make every day.
Every day this much?
Every day this much. Yes.
The carnitas are ready.
Now we're gonna pull them
and shred them.
We got the masa.
And what is the red
in the masa?
Guajillo pepper sauce.
The masa's hot.
It's almost cooked.
Is that how it's made
where you're from in Mexico?
That's the way we do it.
You do it hot?
Yeah.
I'm telling you --
learn something new every day.
I had to
come to Minnesota
to learn about
cooking masa halfway?
Corn husk
soaked in water.
The masa.
Some pork.
That's a big tamale,
boss.
It is, yeah.
How many of these
do you make a week?
Like 1,000.
How many people
work here?
Is this like
the Keebler elves?
Yeah.
How long
are they gonna steam?
One hour.
Okay.
Look at that!
This isn't my birthday.
All right,
I'll try to eat all of them.
And do we serve anything on it,
or just --
No, just like that.
That's probably one of
the most fla--
if not the most flavorful tamale
I've ever had.
I'm savoring every bite.
Most of the time,
the masa has no flavor.
You're waiting to get to
the center of the tamale
to get the meat,
to get the filling.
Yeah, we get the flavor
to the masa and also the meat.
I'm converted.
If there was a county
in Flavortown named Tamale,
that would be it, man.
That is it.
WOMAN:
They're moist, very flavorful.
They're the best tamales
in the Twin Cities.
The tamales have
very good consistency,
especially the masa.
This is where
the "Triple D" crew eats
when they're not shooting
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
This is how often
we come here.
We've all filled out these cards
probably three or four times.
We have our punch cards.
What do you think makes it
so great?
We've been to so many
restaurants with you
that when you find
the real deal, you recognize it.
Authentic Mexican food that
you don't need a passport for.
This is a great place, cheap and
fast, and it's just great food.
This is just perfect.
You love what you do.
I do, yeah.
We have a lot of passion
for what we do, yeah.
Good dude. You got to come down
and meet these cats.
Done a lot of funky joints,
but this here [whistles] up top.
Coming up
in Denver, Colorado...
[ Whistles ]
...a golden Greek joint...
Digging all that.
...putting a modern touch
on the classic.
That barbecue sauce
is gangster.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in the Highlands neighborhood
of Denver, Colorado,
about 10 minutes from downtown.
Now, in this little place, man,
you got it all.
You got some barbershops,
you got some salons, galleries,
boutiques, you've got some
restaurants like Hops & Pie.
I've been to that place.
And right across the street,
you got this joint -- Axios.
ALL: Opa!
I think it's the best Greek food
you can get in Denver.
The Chicken Zymarika.
It's fresh, it's homemade.
I got a Moussaka up.
It gives it the feel
of an expensive meal
at an affordable price.
Calamari soup.
Everything has
a lot of flavor.
FIERI: Including the owner,
Telly Topakas,
who's been serving up
this piece of Greece since 2011.
He's as Greek as it gets.
He'll play the bouzouki for you.
He puts his Greek heritage
into everything.
What kind of Greek restaurant
is this?
I like to call it
a modern Greek restaurant.
It's not heavy,
its not overly oiled.
We have some
traditional recipes,
but then we're doing
a little bit
of some French influence.
You get a plate here
that just looks like something
that you'd want to dig into.
Okay, I got the lamb ribs.
Lamb ribs are like heaven
on a plate.
You do not hear
of lamb ribs.
So, are these spare ribs
or back ribs?
These are shoulder,
actually.
I like the way
it already starts.
So, we're gonna
make a brine?
Yes. First,
we're gonna start with water.
Salt, sugar.
We're doing cinnamon.
Okay.
Allspice,
then we're gonna do nutmeg,
clove, coriander,
star anise, caraway,
then we're just gonna
stir it up.
Gonna brine for 24 hours?
24 hours, yeah.
What are we making now?
It's a fig
barbecue sauce.
Okay.
We're gonna start
with the wine mixture,
which is Sherry, port,
and just a straight red wine.
We're gonna take
a house-made ketchup.
With some
fun, little spices.
Take that all day.
Yeah, it is pretty yummy.
And then we have
a fig puree,
macerated
and cooked in port wine.
Brown sugar.
We got cinnamon,
allspice,
vanilla extract,
cayenne pepper, and salt.
The name of the restaurant,
Axios.
Axios means "worthy."
We're making food
that's worthy.
I feel it's worthy,
and my customers, hopefully,
they feel it's worthy.
And then we're just gonna
put it on the stove.
Let this reduce down.
45 minutes to an hour.
All right, Guy, so these
have been brining overnight,
and we're basically gonna put
together our braising liquids.
Diced tomatoes,
tomato juice,
dry red wine,
some carrots,
chopped onions,
bay leaves,
thyme, garlic,
and rosemary.
How long is this gonna
braise for?
Three and a half hours
at about 375.
Got it.
All right, so we got
our lamb ribs on the grill.
We're just
finishing them off.
Just gonna take
our fig barbecue sauce.
Then we're gonna take
our mashed potatoes.
That barbecue sauce
is gangster.
A little bit of veg.
We have onions, leeks,
mushrooms,
and a little bit of fennel.
Digging all that.
Oh, that's pretty.
Mmm.
Where's that been
all my life?
Roasted garlic, feta,
mashed potatoes.
Veggies have got
great crunch.
Mmm.
[ Muffled ] As you can see,
I'm really not enjoying it.
The char --
nice and meaty.
A little kiss
of that cinnamon in there.
Mmm.
Anybody that says
they don't like lamb,
well, here's your lamb antidote
right here.
Mmm.
Delicious.
Lamb ribs.
The lamb ribs are fabulous.
Great char flavor
from the grill.
The barbecue fig sauce
is perfect sweetness
to offset
the savoriness of the lamb.
Spanakopita in the window.
Feels like you're in,
you know, Little Greece
in any neighborhood
in the country.
I got Souvlaki up.
I think he's brought
a lot to this community
and to this strip.
MAN: We live right here
in the neighborhood,
so we can walk over.
You know you're gonna get
good food every time.
FIERI: Just be sure
to save room for dessert.
Kataifi.
The Torta Kataifi is
a delicately fresh dessert
with citrus and nuts.
It's what cravings are made of.
Torta Kataifi
is what it's called.
What's kataifi?
Kataifi's actually the name
of the pastry they put on top.
It's shredded. It's gonna be
a little bit different
than we typically see
in Greece.
First we're gonna take
some clarified butter,
and this
shredded phyllo pastry.
Mixed around really good
so we get nice and moist,
and then we're
just gonna spread it out
on the bottom of the pan.
Like my hair.
Huh?
We're gonna
bake it off 10 minutes
just to get it
golden brown.
All right, next step.
We're gonna
make the batter.
Start with ricotta cheese,
powdered sugar,
and then we have
some heavy whipping cream.
Okay.
Vanilla extract.
We're gonna
mix this first.
Trying to get it
somewhat smooth.
And now we're gonna fold in
our egg whites.
That'll lighten it up.
Okay.
Now we're building
a Torta Kataifi.
We're gonna take
our pistachio nuts,
and we're just gonna
spread this out a little bit
so we get some
on the bottom,
and then we're gonna pour this
right on top.
There we go.
I like where
this is going, man.
More pistachios.
Sprinkle all across the top.
There you go.
Beautiful.
Now you're
making me hungry.
Okay.
Now we're gonna
take the kataifi pastry.
Right on top evenly.
Okay, you like
where we're at?
I think
it looks beautiful.
And we're just gonna
pop it in the oven
at 325 for 90 minutes,
then we're gonna drop it
to 300 for another 90.
Take the spring form
off of it.
We're gonna finish
with the citrus syrup.
Water, sugar, lemon zest,
orange zest, and lemon juice.
[ Whistles ]
Healthy with
that one, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Let's do a little more.
Mint leaf on top.
And we'll just do
a little whipped cream
for garnish
on the side.
You have full-blown
Greek cheesecake
in every way,
shape, or form.
The shredded phyllo dough,
it's...got a little bite to it.
Tons of pistachios,
and then the bright citrus note,
the ricotta --
Nice and light.
Mmm. Not nearly as dense
as a cheesecake.
Which way's the gym?
I got to find a treadmill.
Here's your Torta Kataifi.
It's really good,
and it's perfectly sweet.
From top to bottom,
the food is great.
Don't use your fingers.
You're gonna end up
eating your fingers.
That's how good it is.
Might be one of the best lines
I've heard in a while.
[ Laughs ]
Not your average Greek
restaurant by any means.
No.
Well done, brother.
Denver's lucky to have you.
[ Speaks Greek ]
Yes, and axios
to you, too.
FIERI:
Up next in Atlanta, Georgia...
All right, then.
...a down-home joint
rocking the recipes...
There's a lot of other things
going on in here besides grits.
...and kicking up
Southern cooking.
It is tequila.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So, I know how you guys like to
show up into a city and say,
"Hey, where did 'Triple D'
just go?"
Well, I'm here in Atlanta,
Georgia, and you know what?
You ask anybody where Buckhead
is, and they'll tell you.
Now, I'm in a little strip mall
to check out a joint
where they've been serving up
Southern specialty
and hospitality
for the last four years.
This is Joy Cafe.
Biscuit and gravy.
We eat here every day.
This is where I go
for my comfort food.
Eggs benedict.
Joy Cafe is the perfect name
for this restaurant.
FIERI:
'Cause it just so happens to be
the name of the owner,
Joy Beber...
Hash browns, please.
Hash browns heard.
...teaming up
with her husband, John,
on their
scratch-made menu.
I'm very Southern,
very traditional.
He likes to throw in
the fancy techniques.
Together, we're deadly.
In a good way?
In a good way.
Okay, I was
just checking.
The quality of the food
for the value that you get,
you can't beat.
Shrimp and grits.
The grits are just
a really nice texture.
The shrimp are super tasty.
Best I've ever had.
FIERI: Okay,
so what are we gonna make?
Making our grits.
We start out with water.
There's a lot
of other things
going on in here
besides grits.
[ Chuckles ]
Heavy cream, butter.
Once that comes to a boil,
we add our grits.
This is garlic powder.
You sure we're not making
culinary wall paste?
[ Laughs ]
Onion powder,
house-made salt.
Probably John out there drying
some seawater in the back.
Pepper,
Worcestershire sauce.
Whoa!
And our house-made
hot sauce.
[ Whistles ]
So, now Louisiana-style
barbecue sauce,
which is what we're gonna
fry the shrimp in.
All right then.
So, first we're gonna
go with --
Butter.
A little butter.
Oil. Paprika.
Okay.
Cayenne, rosemary,
dried oregano,
house salt,
black pepper,
garlic,
and lemon juice.
And that's gonna simmer
15 minutes or so.
And that's what we're gonna
cook the shrimp in.
That's what we're gonna
We're just gonna drop them
right in there.
Right into the pool.
While that's
finishing frying,
we'll go ahead
and plate up our grits.
And fried shrimp.
Rosemary corn.
And then just a small drizzle
of the oil on top.
A sprig of fresh rosemary
and a wedge of lemon.
That is
our shrimp and grits.
Nice creamy grits,
tell you that much.
The shrimp are
perfectly cooked.
The corn's
a great little add.
The hot sauce definitely
goes all the way through,
but not overwhelming.
This is very elevated
grit meal.
Nicely done, girl.
Nicely done.
Thank you. Thank you.
Mmm.
Grits can be really boring,
but these are to die for.
The passion
that Joy and John have
comes out
in all these dishes.
What did you guys do
before you got into this?
Well...
[ Both laugh ]
Oh, boy.
We met in Telecom.
What is that, a city?
[ Chuckling ] No.
I got promoted.
I was her boss and she
really didn't like that,
so she quit.
So I quit.
And then two years later,
we opened this cafe.
Joy and John take
very special care
of the foods that they make.
Biscuit and gravy in the pass.
The biscuits are fluffy
and sweet.
The gravy is packed
with flavor and texture.
And then chorizo, it's homemade.
Delicious.
These are
my mom's biscuits.
We're starting
with AP flour,
baking powder,
baking soda,
kosher salt, and sugar.
Now we're gonna stir up
all the dry ingredients.
FIERI: With that size spoon,
could you stir it
and just go
♪ Oh-wee-oh ♪
[ Laughs ]
Add our shortening.
Just a little bit
of cold butter there for you.
I mix this by hand,
and we're gonna stir in
our buttermilk.
This is
really incredibly loose.
Very messy.
Roll out the dough.
We're gonna cut them
with a biscuit cutter.
Oh, they're humongous.
Gonna go in a 425-degree oven
for 10 minutes.
Then we're gonna drop it to 350
and cook it another 15.
Holy moly!
Now that they've
come out of the oven,
we're gonna brush them
with some honey butter.
Okay.
So, now we're gonna
make the chorizo
for our biscuit and gravy.
We're gonna start
with paprika,
garlic powder, cumin,
fresh-ground black pepper.
I like the fresh-ground.
Oregano, chipotle powder,
and our house-made salt.
And then we're gonna give it
a good whisk.
I like how
you get after it.
So, here's the pork,
and now we're gonna add the
spice mixture that we just made.
This is red-wine vinegar
we're gonna add.
Next is tequila.
It is tequila.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna cover this,
and it's gonna rest
in the cooler overnight.
We're gonna
brown this off.
Remove the chorizo
that's cooked,
leaving the fond
on the bottom.
We're gonna make a roux
with butter, oil, nutmeg,
chipotle powder,
and then we're gonna
caramelize the sugar.
House salt, and pepper.
That's a good-looking roux.
Whisk in flour
and then whole milk.
That's gonna
come to a boil
and get all thick and bubbly
and happy.
Let's plate this up!
All right.
Here's our gravy,
chorizo.
We just throw it right up on --
a little on the floor.
[ Laughs ]
All right.
And now
cheesy hash browns.
Cheesy hash browns.
That's how it comes out.
That is
our biscuit and gravy.
The biscuits are
nice and tender.
Gravy's thick.
This chorizo -- may be
that tequila you put in there
or something,
but it is spot on.
The cheesy hash browns --
That's the bite right there.
Outstanding.
Never had really good gravy
until I came to Joy's.
The biscuits and gravy --
It's always undefeated.
Undefeated.
MAN: It's just
that great Southern feel.
It's love.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
This is exactly where
the "Triple D" crew eats
when they're not shooting
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
I want to say something.
I'm gonna interrupt him now.
Hold on.
[ Laughter ]
Thank you very much.
That's Guy Fieri
signing off
for "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Goodbye!
[ Laughs ]