I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
This is gonna be interesting.
...we're headed west.
Of course we are.
...for a righteous taste of
the Far East.
Oh, my gosh!
In Las Vegas, Nevada...
That didn't just happen, did it?
...the city's first
Japanese spot...
It's dynamite, I can see why you
guys have been here so long.
...still rolling out
old-school style.
This is, again, doing it
the traditional way.
Then just off The Strip...
What are we making?!
...a jackpot joint tucked
inside a casino...
Nicely done, my friend.
...dealing an Asian spin
into good ol' American.
It's my grandma's secret.
No, I got it.
And in Westminster, Colorado...
Pretty gangster.
...a unique barbecue hot spot...
A lot going on in there.
...doing "all you can eat"
Korean style.
I wish I could rent, like,
two extra arms.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D"!
♪♪
You know, you say "Las Vegas,"
and everybody thinks, of course,
The Strip, but I got to
tell you, from living here,
there's so much to find
off the strip, like this joint,
the first Japanese restaurant
in Las Vegas.
48 years and going strong,
this is Osaka Japanese Bistro.
Shrimp tempura pick-up,
please!
It's fabulous.
It'll ruin any other sushi
that you'll ever eat.
White tiger!
It's got to be the most
authentic Japanese restaurant
in the United States.
FIERI: Probably because owner
Gene Nakanishi
learned a thing or two from
a real restaurant pioneer.
Your mom opened the restaurant?
Yeah, she came over from Japan.
She originally worked in
the first Japanese restaurant
in L.A.
Then came and opened the first
one in Las Vegas?
That's correct.
Crazy.
That was way back in 1967,
and today, veteran chef
John Barker
is carrying on
the kitchen tradition...
Beef teriyaki
pick-up, please!
...serving up authentic entrées,
sushi, and rock-star rolls.
Your roppongi.
It's a spicy tuna.
The sauce is just
really zesty.
Oh, I could probably
eat this till I drop.
Monster --
big, beautiful tuna.
I assume from Hawaii.
This is Hawaii big-eyed tuna.
Big-eyed tuna.
Okay, get after it.
Majority of the ingredients
you're bringing in
this whole fish.
The majority of them, yes.
Really?
Now, you guys will
break it down.
So, you guys kind of
take this seriously.
Absolutely.
When looking for
a real-deal sushi joint, this is
what you should see happening.
Now we're gonna make this roll.
We're gonna start by adding
the sriracha to the bowl.
A meal that we make here is
called Yum Yum Sauce --
sweet meal.
Yum Yum Sauce?
Yummy, yummy, yeah.
Okay.
Sesame oil, shichimi --
Japanese pepper --
soy sauce, grated garlic.
Mix this together
and add the sugar.
I like that.
And then smelt eggs.
And this is a sauce with all
the smelt eggs?
That's correct.
[ Utensil clatters ]
Just put it on a plate.
I'll just eat it off of
the plate.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're gonna make spicy tuna.
All right, we got our tuna here
we chopped up,
then we're gonna add
spicy tuna sauce.
Mix this together.
So, that is our spicy tuna.
Now, we're gonna make
the roll finally?
Now, we're gonna make the roll.
We're gonna lay our nori down,
spread our rice across
the seaweed.
Turn that over,
add our shrimp.
And now our spicy tuna.
We roll that.
This is one of the number-one
rolls here.
That is our number-one
selling roll.
We put more tuna on top.
Beautiful tuna.
Our trusty plastic wrapper,
and we'll press this again.
Now, this tataki sauce
that we made earlier.
Right.
Yum Yum Sauce.
Finish off with a little smelt
eggs and some green onions.
Beautiful roll.
I'll tell you, man,
look at that.
Mmm!
It's fantastic.
Taking the time
to make all the sauces,
bring in the whole fish
and break it down,
you guys just do it all the
right way, man, it's dynamite.
I can see why you guys have
been here so long.
Mmm!
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
MAN: Your roppongi has got
a really complex texture to it,
a little spicy, sweet, and sour
all at the same time.
It's an art form
how it's presented
once it's getting ready
to be served.
What is it to have the first
Japanese restaurant in Vegas
that makes you still so popular?
The fact that we're authentic,
do everything old school.
They don't even do it in Japan
the way we do it,
but it tastes better.
Nabeyaki udon pick-up!
[ Speaks Japanese ]
MAN: You've got your noodles,
your broth, your chicken.
It's usually got an egg in it.
It's just a wealth of variety.
It's absolutely delicious.
Okay, what are we on to now?
Okay, now we're gonna prepare
the shrimp for tempura.
Okay, and what's this
going to be for?
Nabeyaki udon.
The noodle dish?
Correct.
Awesome.
We're gonna peel the shrimp.
This is gonna be interesting.
De-vein the shrimp.
Because if he does what
I think he's gonna do,
you'll get a kick out of this.
Cut the back end.
Now, see.
And press it, stretch it out.
This kind of elongates
the shrimp
and makes it more presentable,
and the shrimp doesn't curl up
when you put
the tempura batter.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
All right, tempura batter.
Tempura batter --
ice-cold water.
Add egg yolk to it, and...
Whoa, egg water!
Nothing like a little egg water
on a hot summer day.
[ Tapping ]
Mix it with the tempura flour.
Tempura flour, okay.
Yes.
You gonna dredge
your shrimp first?
Yes.
Okay.
These pans that you have here,
what's the story?
They're copper pans,
they retain the heat
much better than what you get
from a stainless-steel pan.
But this is, again, doing it
a traditional way
and not dropping them into
a fryer?
That's right.
Dig it.
Now we're gonna make
nabeyaki udon.
What's "nabeyaki" mean?
Nabe -- first of the pot
that we use.
Okay.
Yes. Udon is udon.
Yes, yes.
Got it.
We're gonna add the dashi
that we made earlier.
It's a fish stock.
Just a little bit of mirin.
So, this is made to order
each time?
Yes.
This is -- Higashimaru
is a light soy sauce;
kombu, and a little sea salt.
And once it starts to boil,
we're gonna add bonito flakes.
[ Whistles ]
That's a lot.
We're gonna strain this into
our nabe.
And it just goes clear liquid?
Got it.
And we're gonna add
our udon now.
Chicken, fresh shiitake
mushrooms.
Normally, I would put the egg in
right now.
[ Coughs ]
Would you care for an egg?
No egg, thank you.
Thank you.
Fish cake, spinach,
some green onions.
And it gets served in this
screaming-hot bowl?
Yes.
And the tempura shrimp.
Great.
There you go.
Oh, my gosh!
Mmm!
That broth is outrageous.
It is prepared perfectly.
I mean, that's --
that's the way you do it.
Mmm, tempura --
nice and light.
Not over-battered.
[ Slurping ]
[ Chuckles ]
That didn't just happen,
did it?
You're making it from scratch,
treating it with respect,
and just the whole presentation,
all these components --
well done.
Thank you.
Nabeyaki udon.
Oh, man, that looks good.
I love it.
I absolutely love it.
Here's pocket aces for you guys.
I actually grew up in Japan,
so a lot of the food here
is really comparable to the food
that I eat back at home.
It's my buddy Mario from
the world-famous Four Kegs.
What do you think makes it
so great?
They're just wonderful.
They take care of the customers.
It's like family when you walk
in, and that's what we like.
WOMAN: This is what you call
hometown Las Vegas,
and there is nothing
better Osaka's.
It is old school.
This is old Vegas,
and it's got all the feelings,
and your Chef John is fantastic.
The food was dynamite.
Glad you guys came.
Awesome, brother.
Thanks.
Coming up,
we're staying in Vegas...
Let's get after this.
...for an Asian-American
diner...
You have an eclectic mix.
...putting a flavorful twist
on traditional comfort.
That is a bomb grilled cheese.
♪♪
FIERI: So, I think everybody
knows by now,
I went to college here in
Las Vegas,
and I'm about a 1/2 mile off
The Strip.
Now, I drove by this place
a million times,
never stopped in here --
it's called the Eureka Casino,
and, boy, did I miss out.
This is the home of Fat Choy
Asian American Fare.
[ Sizzling ]
I have your sesame noodles
here for you.
Looks like a diner but tastes
like it's gourmet.
One Fat Choy burger!
If I was ever in the hospital,
I'd want someone to sneak
this in to me.
Chicken teriyaki rice.
Sheridan's an amazing chef.
FIERI: That'd be Sheridan Su,
who worked at kitchens
from New York to Los Angeles
before rolling the dice
in Vegas in 2011.
They started off as
a food truck.
And then he had a little kiosk t
hat was in the middle of
a beauty salon,
and now he's got a full kitchen
and a full restaurant.
One Pork Belly Bao!
I typically get two orders
of the Pork Belly Bao.
MAN: A Chinese steamed bun with
marinated pork belly --
total goodness.
[ Air rushing ]
So, this is how loud
it's gonna be the whole time?
We're in a wind tunnel!
What are we making?!
We're making Pork Belly Bao!
All right, man, get into it.
We're gonna start with a
marinade -- 2 cups of soy sauce.
There we go.
4 cups of water.
And brown sugar.
Garlic powder and green onion.
There we go.
So, let that simmer down?
Yes.
I said, "Let it simmer down!"
We're gonna pour it
right on top of the pork.
You have to let it cool down
or you're gonna poach it.
Yes.
And then I'll cover it.
Now, this will marinate for
24 hours, then go in the oven?
For three hours,
300 degrees.
And then what's going on
here with the pork?
The pork -- we'll put a pan
over it just to compress it.
So, we'll put it into
our fridge overnight.
And from here,
we'll take the pans out.
So, we'll take this baby out,
right onto the cutting board,
where I'll just trim off
the edges.
Got it.
Cut them into nice blocks.
So, we'll sear that off
in a pan?
Yes.
Brown it on both sides.
All right, now,
what are we doing?
Now we're gonna chop
the preserved mustard greens.
Okay.
We're gonna go ahead
and sauté them.
Got it.
So, first, the oil,
garlic, onion.
And in goes
the mustard green.
[ Sizzling ]
And a little...
Sweet soy sauce.
And how long are you gonna
let that sauté down?
About three minutes.
Okay.
We have our steamed buns.
We're gonna open the bao.
First, it goes
hoisin sauce.
Thai roll.
Put the pork belly right on top.
On top of that, gets preserved
mustard greens.
And add crushed peanuts.
And then finally cilantro
right on top of that.
And this is one of
the number-one sellers?
Yes.
That's it --
the Pork Belly Bao.
And that's all she wrote, okay.
Let's get after this.
Great steamed bun -- nice,
tender, nice and light.
The pork is tender.
It's sweet.
I like the counterbalance
with the mustard green --
really good, man.
Awesome.
[ Muffled ] I feel you.
Nice.
All right, Pork Belly Bao.
Luscious and delicious
and outstanding and [sighs]...
MAN: It's like the ultimate
slider, right?
It's like supersized bacon.
It's pretty cool.
BLT!
MAN: Sheridan's made
a reputation of taking
American food and giving
a little Asian twist to it.
Short-rib grilled cheese!
MAN: The short-rib
grilled-cheese sandwich
is a great example of that.
Short-rib grilled cheese?
Yes.
In an Asian bistro?
In an Asian bistro.
When we started this restaurant,
it was a diner,
so we kept a lot of
the diner dishes,
and we threw in a lot of Asian
twists to it.
Okay, so, we're gonna
trim this down.
So, we're gonna take all the fat
and some of the skin off,
and then we're gonna cut it
right through the bone.
Oh, this is on the bone, too?
Great.
And we're gonna give this
a nice sear
till it's brown
on all sides.
[ Sizzling ]
So, after the short ribs
are done browning,
we're gonna put it
right into the pan.
A lot of work for
a grilled cheese.
On top of that, we're gonna
put our marinade.
Okay.
Let's start with Cola.
Really?
It's my grandma's secret.
No, I got it.
And add rice wine.
Soy sauce.
A little bit of water,
and add ginger.
Garlic and green onions.
So, we're gonna let that braise
for three hours,
300 degrees,
till it falls off the bone.
I mean, that's done.
Nice.
Okay.
We're gonna start with
the onion jam.
A little bit of oil.
We're going with the red onions.
We'll add a little bit of honey
to help it caramelize.
And add a little bit of
brown sugar.
Whoa!
Give that a stir.
A little red wine.
And we'll finish it with
balsamic vinegar.
Another one of those famous
Asian ingredients.
[ Chuckles ]
Some black pepper and salt.
That'll be the onion jam going
for the grilled cheese
we're having at the Asian bistro
in a casino in Las Vegas.
Absolutely.
You hear it every day.
So, I wanted a couple of
nice slices of sourdough.
Is it a butter sandwich?
[ Laughs ]
So, this goes right into
the pan.
American cheese, cheddar cheese,
and Swiss cheese.
So, the short ribs
that we have shredded.
Again, a spoonful of this
onion jam.
We'll just mix this
all together,
and then this goes right
on top of the cheese.
A lot of short rib.
So, we'll just let that
cook slowly, and --
Put in a little salad
and a little vinaigrette.
Our dipping sauce, marinara.
Nicely done, my friend.
The bread --
nice and crunchy.
I like you put
a lot of butter on there.
The onion marmalade
is what makes it.
Your short rib is seasoned
perfectly, and you get a ton.
That is a bomb grilled cheese.
All right,
short rib grilled cheese.
I can't decide whether to just
take small bites
or shove the whole thing
into my mouth.
And this is actually
what I eat every time.
It's the best.
Roasted Duck Bao.
I'm not just raving on because
it's bloody television, mate.
Everything on the menu,
it's fantastic.
FIERI: You come in here.
You have an eclectic mix,
definitely not what I expected.
Nice job.
I'm glad you like it.
Up next, in Westminster,
Colorado...
Wow, you got that process down.
...we're firing up the grills...
You just are nonstop!
...for Korean barbecue
that just doesn't quit.
There were a few things I was
expecting him to tell me.
Pig out was not one of them.
♪♪
I love Colorado.
I mean, they got so much
going on here,
especially the food scene.
I mean, who could forget
Fat Sully's?
Give me some pie!
Then you got Lauer-Krauts --
love that place.
So, there's no doubt that these
guys got a Korean restaurant
and not just any
Korean restaurant --
this one's off the hook --
this is Dae Gee Korean B.B.Q.
[ Sizzling ]
Get your chicken!
If you want
authentic Korean food,
this is definitely
the place to come to.
Beef's up!
This is just overwhelmingly
delicious.
You get to come here and cook it
on the grill,
and it's just an experience.
I'll eat everything they put
in front of me.
FIERI: Which is just how owner
Joe Kim wants it.
Somebody says,
"Okay, I'm gonna go to Dae Gee."
"Oh, that place -- you..."?
Pig out.
There were a few things I was
expecting him to tell me.
Pig out was not one of them.
But that's exactly what his
customers have been doing since
he and his mother-in-law heated
up the hibachis in 2010.
What makes it so dynamite?
All you can eat.
Unlimited barbecue!
Every different kind of meat you
can imagine, they bring out.
Just covered with sides.
There's nonstop food coming.
You just keep eating,
and it's awesome.
What are we making first?
We're gonna make
the beef bulgogi first.
What does "bulgogi" mean?
"Bul" means fire,
and then "gogi" means meat.
Fire meat?
Yeah. Got the water.
This is the sauce for
the bulgogi?
Right.
The garlic.
The onions.
Pineapples.
Got the apples.
Apples?
Yeah. The soy sauce, sugar,
black pepper.
Sesame oil?
Yeah.
And most importantly, Soju.
Soju?
Kind of a Korean spirit, yeah.
"Soju" gonna put it
in there now?
Yeah.
[ Blender whirring ]
Hey, what meat is this?
A rib-eye.
You slice it thin.
How long are we gonna
let that marinade?
12 hours.
12 hours?
Yeah.
What are we making next?
Chicken bulgogi.
Add some garlic,
the soy-bean oil, sesame oil,
ginger, black peppers.
Sugar?
Soy sauce.
And the Soju.
"Soju" just put
a little bit in?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
Over the chicken?
Yeah.
24 hours?
Next, we're gonna make
the Dae Gee sauce.
Dae Gee sauce.
Dae Gee sauce, yeah.
So, this is like
the house sauce?
House sauce.
Kind of like
the Korean Thousand Island.
Exactly -- put it on everything.
The soy sauce,
the vinegar, sugar.
Soy-bean oil.
You add some corn syrup.
That's what you use in
your hair, huh?
Oh, yeah.
Sesame seed
and Korean red peppers.
And that's the bags of Korean
red peppers you have up there?
Absolutely.
I'll be stealing them.
[ Laughs ]
Next, Chef, what are we making?
Kimchi.
Is that, like, the French fries
to the burger?
Absolutely.
So, first, the Napa cabbage.
We're gonna cut it into fourths.
Salt it.
Wow, you got that process down.
And let it sit
for 12 hours.
Now, let's make the marinade.
Gonna add some onions, garlic,
little shrimps.
A little shrimp?
Scrimps?
Yeah.
Add some daikon radish, ginger.
A little bit of rice just
to tighten it up?
Yeah.
Some seafood broth.
Fish sauce.
And then some of the...
Korean red peppers.
That I'm stealing.
Yeah.
Then we're gonna add some sugar.
Okay.
We have the cabbage.
It's already been rinsed
and strained.
Then just kind of go at it.
Where did you learn this?
My mother-in-law.
She had a restaurant in Hawaii
for about 15, 20 years.
What's next?
We're gonna make some
kimchi pancakes.
Of course we are.
This is our kimchi
that's been fermenting
for about a month right now.
All right, and this is one of
the side-dish items
that comes out?
Correct.
A little tofu?
Yeah.
Jalapeños and onions?
Right.
Soon as that's pureed,
add some sugar.
Some Korean red peppers.
That's what's in your hair.
I knew it.
Egg?
Yeah. Some potato starch.
Potato starch?
Yeah.
Then we're gonna add some flour.
A.P.?
Yeah.
All right. And these are
gonna get fried up?
Sautéed, yeah.
[ Sizzling ]
So, actually, there's another
side that we're gonna make,
which is a fish cake.
That's just -- that's awesome.
We'll eat next week.
All right, we got the wok.
Heat that up.
There's some BTUs, baby.
We're gonna add some onions,
some green onions,
carrots, jalapeños.
Add some garlic.
Stir it in a little bit.
[ Sizzling ]
Fish cakes.
Soy sauce,
some black peppers.
Add some sugar, yeah.
Corn syrup, seafood broth,
crushed red peppers,
and then Korean red peppers.
Top it off with
some sesame oil.
[ Sizzling ]
And that's it.
Now what do we do?
Yeah, we're gonna cook it at
the barbecue tables.
Okay. Go, we just bring it out,
or what do we do?
Yeah, I'll make a plate
and everything,
and I'll set it all up,
and I'll bring it out to you.
You're gonna show up,
though, right?
Oh, yeah.
FIERI: Oh, yeah --
when we come back,
we're finally gonna get it going
on the grill.
You will bring it?
Yeah.
To the table?
To the tables.
That I'm at?
Yeah.
Now?
Right.
[ Chuckles ]
Check.
FIERI: The grills are lit just
outside Denver, Colorado...
Unlimited barbecue!
...at Dae Gee Korean B.B.Q.
You just are nonstop!
I take my job very seriously.
Yes, you do, Chef.
But I haven't eaten a thing yet
'cause all we've been doing
is making preparations for
the ultimate feast.
The unlimited barbecue.
All you can eat,
six different types of meats,
and there's actually
an assortment of side dishes
that come out with it.
So, let's recap this --
we made the beef bulgogi,
chicken bulgogi, the Dae Gee
house barbecue sauce,
Napa cabbage kimchi,
kimchi pancakes,
fish cakes, and there's plenty
of all that to go around.
It's truly unlimited.
[ Laughs ]
You can keep eating forever.
I purposely don't eat sometimes
before I come here.
MAN: The grill's hot.
Throw it right on there.
It's sizzling.
It's an interactive experience.
If you're gonna eat it,
they're gonna bring it.
What do we do first?
We get some onions right here.
So, you season the grill
with the onion?
Yeah, and then you get
some vegetables on there.
Beef bulgogi and then
the chicken bulgogi.
So, typically, you take
a lettuce wrap,
put a little bit of the meat
that you like,
some of the sides.
Mmm! Kimchi cake --
pretty gangster.
[ Sizzling ]
Whole point is the pig-out.
Mmm!
A lot going on in there.
The bulgogi is
out of bounds.
I love that you used
the rib-eye.
You get a little salt,
a little vinegar.
Mmm!
The Dae Gee sauce.
Steal that.
Mmm!
I just like that you have
the variety.
The bright, fresh, acid flavors,
you got the cooked veggies.
You got the raw veggies,
the briny kimchi,
then the cornucopia
of meats.
Where's the venting going?
Venting through these sides
right here.
So, it's a built-in table
that does it all?
I got to get one these
for my house.
You take the time
and make it yourself.
That's the difference.
Outstanding.
I wish I could rent,
like, two extra arms.
[ Laughs ]
If you're a meat eater, you
should definitely come eat here.
It's protein heaven.
MAN: You can always find
something that you like,
and if you like something,
you tell them to bring more.
WOMAN: You're involved in what
you're cooking,
and you can socialize and enjoy
food and share it with everyone.
If you're gonna have a haircut
like that,
you'd better back it up.
Yeah, absolutely.
Legit, buddy.
All right, man.
Legit.
[ Chuckles ]
Keep cooking.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Sighs ]
It's been like 90 seconds.
Where's the food?
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]