I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
...we're celebrating Christmas
and Hanukkah...
Package deal.
...with dishes
fit for a feast...
Holy moly, that's good.
...and Jewish delis
all about family tradition...
That's the key
right there.
...in Nashville.
-Get out!
We've got heavyweight
holiday tamales...
This has got to be
one of the best I've ever had.
...and a sugar-glazed knockout
that will fire you up.
Now you're cooking with gas!
Then from Florida to Cali...
Show me the goods.
...there's matzo balls
and latkes...
There you go!
...cabbage and knishes...
It's a delish knish.
...all totally legit.
The ones I've had
do not compare to that.
Plus, in Alaska...
You're gonna love this.
...traditional turkey
with a sweet chaser.
That is outstanding.
So get ready
to dig in to the season...
You're not Santa, are you?
...with this holiday
extravaganza.
That's the corner
of delicious and juicy
right in the middle
of Flavortown.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
Hey. I'm Guy Fieri,
north of the lower 48
in Alaska, in Fairbanks.
And if there's one thing I'll
go anywhere for, it's barbecue.
So here we are -- Big Daddy's
Northernmost Southern Barbecue!
HAROLD:
Full rack Arkansas ribs.
MAN: If you like barbecue,
this is where you want to be
for Christmas.
WOMAN: St. Louis ribs.
A little bit of south
in the north.
Brisket,
collard greens, okra.
Normal food
up here in Fairbanks, Alaska?
No, it's not,
but at Big Daddy's, it is.
HAROLD:
Pulled pork sandwich up.
What do you think
makes his barbecue so good?
Harold.
Harold makes the barbecue good.
-That would be Harold Groetsema.
-How's everything going tonight?
Your friends call you
Big Daddy?
Yes, sir.
And for the holidays,
he's serving up some big birds.
-We do whole smoked turkeys.
-Really?
-People come and get them whole?
-Yep.
The alternative
to the big roast turkey.
FIERI:
This one's brined and smoked.
When it comes
to holiday time,
brining turkeys, to me,
is just one of the best.
Give me the rundown
here, boss.
Some water in the pan here.
Okay, we got
the kosher salt.
-Got the sugar.
-Brown sugar.
Flame her up.
Stir it till it dissolves.
Well, now we add
the other ingredients.
We'll add some soy sauce,
some apple cider vinegar.
Apple cider vinegar and barbecue
go hand in hand.
Black pepper,
granulated garlic.
Some allspice,
and we got some honey.
Okay.
That's still nice and hot.
Cool it down with some ice.
And that should be good enough.
Get it down
to about 40 degrees or so.
Come on over
to my house later.
We're gonna have
some turkey punch.
[ Laughs ]
Get our brining bucket,
pour this in there.
We'll take our turkey
by the legs, drop her in there.
Make sure it gets down
in the cavity. You'll love this.
Then we want to make sure
it's covered completely.
This guy's
got all the tricks.
Put this in there,
cover it up.
So this goes in the walk-in
for about 18 hours.
18 to 24 hours, yes.
So we're gonna make the dry rub.
Yeah. Got the sugar,
granulated garlic.
Got your mustard, chili.
No cayenne on this?
No cayenne.
Not that much heat.
Got your paprika, brown sugar,
black pepper.
And we just
mix it all together.
We sift it just to mix
all the ingredients real good.
-So you use this rub for...
-Just for poultry.
There's no salt, 'cause
the brine had enough salt.
Well, what I like to do
is I like to separate the skin
so the skin
gets a little bit crispier.
The skin will dry out.
The skin works as a natural
barrier to keep the moisture in,
and it's real hard
for that dry rub
to make it
through that skin.
Take a little dry rub,
give the meat some flavor.
I like
folding the wings over.
Just so they don't get
all burned off.
That, and it's
a good presentation
when you pull it
out of the smoker.
Put a little olive oil,
give it a nice massage.
-Turkeys love good massages.
-Yes, they do.
Then I'll just sprinkle some
on top.
Kind of creates a little wet rub
with the olive oil.
Pull the legs over,
tie it up with a couple pieces
of rubber band. And there we go.
Now we're gonna go
hit her in the smoker.
-Yep.
-There we go.
-Got her?
-Ohh.
300 degrees
for about two hours?
-You got her.
-All right.
-We ready to go?
-Yep.
-There you are.
-Oh, it smells great.
-What are we gonna do with it?
-Eat it.
Yeah, but I mean,
do you give me a drumstick?
What to you want,
a little slice on top?
Give me what you got, man.
Look at how juicy
that turkey is.
Mmm.
Oh, my gosh!
That is outstanding.
Not salty, not sweet.
Mmm. Fantastic.
That's award-winning turkey
right there. Mega flavor.
Then we make a sandwich.
This is for the holidays.
We're gonna start putting it
on our menu as a regular item.
You seriously can't put
any more turkey on that.
-Usually do.
-Don't let me get in the way.
-We stack her.
-Okay.
Look at that thing.
Mmm. Oh.
Holy moly, that's good!
That's the corner
of delicious and juicy
right in the middle
of Flavortown.
If that doesn't say holiday
in a sandwich,
I don't know what does.
You're not Santa, are you?
[ Twinkle! ]
Your sled is double parked.
-Smoked turkey sandwich.
-Really tender and juicy.
The thing I think that jumps out
is the smoke flavor.
The flavor is kind of soaked
all the way through.
-Look at that.
-Hey, you're telling me.
I ate the whole turkey.
I had Thanksgiving and Christmas
in the back all by myself.
The chicken and rib plate
with baked beans.
MAN: It's kind of nice to come
and have some southern barbecue
-in the middle of a cold winter.
-Coming up.
FIERI: From -- get this --
a Chicago south-sider...
Burnt ends up!
...who didn't know a thing
about barbecue
until he moved to Alaska
and met a guy
who was running a smokehouse.
He taught me
the good smoked barbecue.
Now I have a passion for it.
It's just, I love it.
-So do his fans.
-Mmm.
-Everything good?
-Yes.
FIERI: He won best brisket at
the state barbecue championship
three years in a row.
It's everything
you could hope for in brisket.
Mmm.
Brisket can be
a great holiday meal.
FIERI: And Big Daddy's smoking
more than 10 tons a year.
I like using certified Angus
beef when I do briskets.
I don't trim
unless I'm doing a competition.
I like to have
all the flavor,
as much flavor as I can
out of the fat.
Dry rub is the same as the one
we just did for the turkey,
-but this has the salt in it.
-Salt added to it, yep.
We just flop her in there
and just turn.
-Oh, we just -- We load it on.
-Wow!
-Looking good.
-I take it to the smoker.
Let's do it.
Look at that.
HAROLD: Put it fat side up.
So it moisturizes itself
as it cooks.
-How long?
-Between 12 and 14 hours.
And one thing I learned
about barbecue
is it's done when it's done.
Oh, I like that. Look at
the bark on that. All right.
-Looks good to me.
-Slice it up.
I'm gonna give you basically
what we put in for competition.
Okay. Show it to me.
I am a KCBS judge, by the way.
He knows
what I'm talking about,
so he's gonna give me the best
of his brisket right now.
Oh!
Juice just running out of that.
Can I take a little look
at that? Nice bark on that.
Don't want it
to just fall apart in your hand,
but you should be able to just
very lightly pull it apart.
Mmm. Way to go.
Light smoke.
Not overdone. Mmm.
Brisket's coming up.
-I love the brisket.
-You love the brisket.
A little bit of fat on it.
That's the way I like it.
We got to talk
about dessert now.
-What do you got for me?
-Holiday bread pudding.
Oh.
Probably the best yet.
HAROLD:
We'll add some butter,
start making the custard
for the bread pudding.
-Okay.
-We'll add the heavy cream.
Dude, heavy cream?
-Sure that's not yogurt?
-Cows up here need to keep warm.
What, it just comes out like
ice cream right off the bat?
Just let that heat up.
Meantime, we're gonna add
some ingredients over here
to add to the custard.
-First, 24 egg yolks.
-Mmm.
And we'll add our brown sugar.
And we'll add some vanilla.
[ Whistles ] Wow.
You can smell the vanilla
coming right out of that.
Nutmeg, some cinnamon.
-Minaminamin...
-[ Murmuring ]
-Sugar.
-'Cause we didn't
have it handled with the 2 cups
of the brown sugar.
It's a sweet sauce.
Then we're gonna temper it
into our sauce.
You whisk. I'll pour.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
We're going. We're going.
We're going.
And the last thing we add
is the bourbon.
French bread that you use
here in the restaurant?
Yes, sir.
We got our tempered mixture
with our cream.
Let it soak
for a little bit.
-That's a lot of liquid.
-A lot of bread.
Mix it up a little bit.
Pour it into a 2-inch pan.
Sprinkle some raisins in there.
Add some pears.
Wrap it with Saran wrap
and then foil on top.
And then foil. So you're really
gonna lock in all the moisture.
Pop it in the oven for 325
for about an hour and a half.
Gonna make some bourbon sauce.
So we're gonna melt some butter.
-Some sugar in there.
-Just a little bit.
Add some milk.
Stir it up.
Keep stirring it
so it doesn't scorch.
Shut the heat off,
and I'll add one egg at a time.
Keep stirring.
See the teamwork
that's going on right here?
Oh, yeah.
Then we'll add our whiskey.
-Let that sit.
-Pull it out and serve it up.
Serve it up. What we'll do
is just cut it up.
-There we go.
-Bourbon sauce.
That's a pretty big portion
you're giving there.
Usually two people eat it.
Or one person
becomes two people.
Exactly. We make it look
a little more holiday cheer.
-Decorate it with some fondant.
-Like you find on a cake.
Just put a couple mint leaves
in there, and there we go.
Hey, look at that!
Still really hot.
-Got to serve it warm.
-Yep. I'd say that's warm.
Mmm. This is a gigantic, big
bourbon French toast.
[ Both chuckle ]
Really tasty, man.
Nice holiday dessert.
-Nice job.
-Hey, thank you.
Bread pudding.
WOMAN: I love
that it looks like a present.
-It's full of holiday cheer.
-Being from Texas,
it's the southern spice I like,
the bourbon sauce.
I got your food ready here.
The food just really
makes it worthwhile.
Pulled pork with baked beans.
It's absolutely fantastic.
Kansas City, table 12.
It really is the northernmost
southern barbecue.
FIERI: Santa Claus eats
his barbecue here, I hear.
-Comes here every so often.
-That's why I see
that you don't have
reindeer sausage on the menu.
-He gets a little offended.
-He does get a little worked up.
He gets a little worked up
on that.
FIERI:
Up next in Denver, Colorado...
I better get
a Hanukkah card.
...a real-deal joint
with a bomb brisket...
That is the bite right there.
...is just one page
out of Grandma's cookbook.
It's like a matzo ball
gone wild.
When I say Denver, Colorado,
what comes to mind?
Well, definitely the Broncos
and Mile High Stadium,
and the gateway to great skiing.
But do you think Jewish deli,
you know,
making the matzo ball soup
and the knishes?
Well, you may not
have thought it before,
but that could all change today,
'cause we're here to check out
the Bagel Deli & Restaurant.
-Jumbo brisket on pumpernickel.
-Tremendous.
-Here's the matzo ball soup.
-I love it.
-It's just the best in town.
-Pastrami coming up.
Is this
real-deal Jewish food?
-Oh, yeah.
-It's tradition.
FIERI: Started by Rhoda Kaplan's
parents 44 years ago...
There's the kishka.
...and proudly continued
by Rhoda...
I need the au jus.
--...and her husband, Joe.
-Got a tongue sandwich up.
-The tradition's carried on.
-It hasn't changed at all.
'Cause Rhoda's still using
her Bubbe's recipes.
-Bubbe is grandma.
-Bubbe means grandmother.
FIERI:
Like this Bubbe's classic...
-Matzo ball soup.
-Absolutely fabulous.
...that Rhoda's been making
since she was 3 years old.
-What are we into?
-Eggs.
-[ Whistles ]
-White pepper, ginger.
Are matzo balls
always with ginger?
They should be.
-Salt, oil.
-Okay.
-Mix this real good.
-Very nice.
♪ Row, row,
row your chickens ♪
Now matzo meal. You have to mix
really carefully.
-Or you'll get...
-Lumps.
...inconsistency, clumpage,
and break-aparts.
Then what we're gonna do
is we're gonna take it.
We're gonna put it
into another bowl.
Because?
Because I like
this little bowl better.
It's easier for me
to roll my matzo balls.
You just like doing dishes.
So we put that in the
refrigerator for how long?
-Four to five hours.
-So it's chilled up,
congealed enough
that it will be able to scoop.
Correct. So now we're gonna
roll the matzo balls.
We scooped them.
Now we have to roll them.
Correct. Put your hands
in the oil like that.
-Smoothing them out.
-That's it.
-How long do they take to cook?
-About 35 minutes.
And while those are cooking,
we start on the chicken stock?
-Sure.
-Okay.
Kosher chicken,
celery, carrots, onions,
and I need your help
with that water.
-Please?
-See? Lucky I'm here.
-And it's already warm.
-There you go.
Had to put
a little flair on it.
It's gonna cook
for about 3, 3 1/2 hours.
Pull our chickens out. Take
the vegetables out separate.
Then what we do is
we'll take 3/4 of this stock,
add a little bit
of a chicken base, carrots.
Put it in the chicken
that we shredded,
parsley with
a little bit of water.
-Okay.
-Mix them up, and we're done.
-Dig it.
-Now we take the matzo balls.
-See how big they got?
-Yeah.
How many gallons of this
do you go through?
-15, 20 gallons a day.
-What?
I know
when there's a flu epidemic.
Everybody comes in
for matzo ball soup.
Mmm, this is killer.
The matzo ball
is super light and tender,
but it has great texture.
-The flavor is outrageous.
-I'm glad you like it.
I don't even feel sick,
I feel better already.
Good.
[ Laughs ]
-Matzo ball soup.
-Matzo balls are perfect.
The broth is wonderful.
You just know
that it was made with care.
Here's your corned beef
and egg salad.
The food
is absolutely tremendous.
Jumbo turkey.
-What makes it so good?
-It's made with love.
Chopped liver and egg salad.
We love you.
We think about you.
Give Rho-Rho a kiss!
I missed you!
We just know you,
and we treat you like family.
FIERI: And it's been like that
for generations.
My grandmother
started a tradition
where we all have brunch
on Sunday.
-Every Sunday?
-Every Sunday.
When you can get
two of Bubbe's best...
-Brisket knishes here.
-...stuffed into one.
We have
such fabulous brisket,
we decided to make a knish
out of it.
-It's a delish knish.
-Hey, that's good.
Okay, so, give me the rundown.
How we doing this?
First of all, we're gonna
take these briskets.
Fat up
so as it cooks down,
you render down the fat,
moisturizes it. Got it?
-Okay, first in?
-Carrots in.
-And just whole like that?
-Whole like that.
-Celery in, whole like that.
Then we put these lovely
peeled yellow onions in.
Thank goodness
we cut the onion.
At least someone cut the onion.
Now?
The pepper, garlic powder --
yummy.
-And then this an au jus mix.
-Beef base.
Yeah.
We just cover it with water.
Okay, so everybody's
in the pool.
It's really important to
cover it really, really tight.
So, this goes in the oven,
400, 5 1/2 hours.
Can you go
get the briskets out for me?
-Come on!
-I know!
-Be careful.
-Ooh.
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot.
Juicy, juicy, juicy, juicy.
Perfect.
-Thanks, dear.
-I better get a Hanukkah card.
Take this off.
We're gonna put them over here.
We're gonna drain
this stuff,
'cause we're gonna make
a base for our kishka.
-Look at that. Smells awesome.
-That's good.
Trim these, and then
we're gonna make the mix
for the meat knishes
out of that.
Don't you think we should
pick at it and eat some first?
Well, yeah.
Really nice beef flavor.
Cut this into pieces.
Now this all
goes to the buffalo chopper?
Go. Nothing like
big kitchen equipment.
That's about
the consistency.
Now we're gonna
take this out of here.
On goes the gloves, 'cause
this gets kind of messy now.
White pepper. Garlic.
Season-All.
-Eggs.
-A little chicken binder there.
Yep, sauteed onions. So, that
gets all mixed up really good.
And then,
these pastries here?
Put them here on the metal.
Then we're gonna paint.
This is just eggs and milk,
a little egg wash.
Scoop it in, bring the ends up,
twist it,
smash it so it looks
about like that.
-Oh, wow. That smashed?
-More. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Put this
on that cookie sheet.
A little bit
of the same egg wash,
and we knock out
50 or 60 a day.
Bake them off
at, what, 350?
350 for about
35, 40 minutes.
-And that's a knish.
-Mmm!
-Smells good, huh?
-Mmm.
-That's great.
-Good.
Nice and flaky,
not overly salty. Mmm.
-So, this is red horseradish.
-Mmm!
Good stuff, that
red horseradish, huh?
Where have you been with the
purple horseradish all my life?
That is the bite right there,
when you complement it
with the two.
Mmm! Nice job.
Brisket knish is up.
Kind of like a croissant
on steroids.
-Just tastes like home cooking.
-Roast beef coming up.
You walk in here.
You know everybody.
You've been eating this food
since you were a little kid.
-From Reubens...
-It's very tasty.
-...to potato latkes.
-Best in the world.
-And something called kishka...
-There's the kishka.
-Kind of like stuffing.
-Never had this.
Almost tastes like a Jewish
meatloaf. It's just fabulous.
...done Rhoda's way.
Okay, go to it.
Okay, you ready?
We're gonna turn on my favorite.
Buffalo chopper?
I love this.
Carrots whole.
Get ready. You might cry.
-Onions.
-I've seen this movie before.
This has to grind
for just a little bit, okay?
Then we're gonna put in
white pepper,
poultry seasoning,
paprika,
au jus mix,
garlic powder.
Kosher salt.
Mix that up a little bit.
Now we add eggs. Matzo meal.
Now the flour.
This is melted schmaltz.
Oops. Sorry.
You got schmaltz
all over me!
-So, that's melted chicken fat.
-Correct.
Conveniently packed.
Pudding cup, kids!
[ Chuckles ]
-Okay, now we add the oil.
-Regular canola oil?
Regular, old canola oil.
See if it's right.
It's got to be about that
consistency. And we're good.
-Can you eat it now?
-Oh, yeah.
-Yeah, let's not.
-[ Chuckles ]
Now what's up?
Years ago, you would put it
in actual cow's intestine.
We call that casing. But we're
not putting it in the casing.
No, take a piece, make it look
kind of like a log, and...
-Wrap it up in tin foil.
-And roll it pretty darn tight.
Twist one end,
twist another end.
They're gonna bake for how long?
35 minutes.
Turn them over, and then about
another 35, 40 minutes.
There's schmaltz
all over that.
There is schmaltz
So we're gonna take this one.
We're gonna uncover it.
So now you see
why you had to turn it,
'cause you don't want it getting
too burnt on both sides.
This is crazy!
Cut it.
Put it on there.
This is that yummy au jus
we made out of the brisket.
Pour that over it. That's
all yours for the tasting.
Mmm. Where's this big Jewish
dumpling been all my life?
Mmm. Really takes on the flavor
of the chicken stock.
It's like a matzo ball
gone wild.
-[ Laughs ]
-I'm surprised.
Out of all the Jewish delis
we've shot on "Triple D,"
and of all the Jewish meals
I've enjoyed,
and that kishka...
I get a kick out of kishka!
That's how you do it.
Nice job.
Oh, the kishka is so good.
-It's very rich.
-Tender and moist.
-It's outstanding.
-Mini knishes coming up.
The food is always
consistently great.
This is a very special place.
-It's tough to beat.
-Lean corned beef coming up.
Congratulations.
Awesome place.
-Thanks.
-Got to check it out.
FIERI: Coming up
in Nashville, Tennessee...
[ Both mumbling indistinctly ]
...a funky Mexican spot...
That just hit a new level.
...dishing out a tasty December.
-The holiday tamale.
-Holiday tamales.
So, I'm here
in East Nashville, Tennessee.
Now, I think I'm like you guys.
I'm going to a town --
I start calling family
and friends and saying,
"Hey. Where should I go?
Where is my next
'Triple D' joint?"
Well, you know
I love Martin's Bar-B-Que,
so I call up my boy, Pat.
I said, "Pat, I need a joint.
Where should I..."
He says, "Listen.
Do not leave town
without checking out
this joint."
This is Mas Tacos Por Favor.
Got tacos for Andrea.
The food is wonderful.
FIERI: That's what this guy
keeps telling me.
Pat Martin
of Martin's Bar-B-Que.
Why do you think
this place rocks?
They make everything
from scratch.
Fresh food, local food,
and I wonder how do they do it.
FIERI:
By going right to the source,
which is exactly where
self-trained chef
Teresa Mason headed.
She did her homework.
She went down
and lived in Mexico
and came back up here
and knocked it out.
In a 1974 Winnebago
turned mobile kitchen.
She was a very, very popular
stop after a late night out.
FIERI:
In 2010, she found an old deli
and continued to crank out
authentic Mexican.
Hey, Ben, I got
one tamale going out.
One of the best places in town
for tamales.
Hot tamale.
FIERI: But you can only get them
on Wednesdays or the holidays.
It's amazing.
FIERI:
A Christmas tradition
of masa and spicy filling
steamed in husks
and topped
with a green tomatillo salsa.
We're gonna make these special
for Christmastime.
The Holiday Tamale?
The Holiday Tamales.
Now we're gonna make
the masa.
It's just cornmeal that's been
ground special for tamales.
We'll put
a little baking powder
because I like them
to fluff up a little bit.
To puff up a bit.
Yep.
Put a little salt.
And I just mix that up.
So, we've got our broth.
We make this.
It's a homemade
chicken broth.
We put a little lime
and a lot of peppers in this.
I like to stir a little bit.
Here, I'll stir that.
What's next?
Okay, we need lard.
Is that chicken fat?
It's chicken fat.
The thing I like to do --
I whip it up
so it'll be nice and airy.
Get out!
Get out.
It works, too.
These are really good.
-I'm impressed.
-These are really nice.
So, now you can just start
scooping that right into here.
These are gonna be fluffy.
Fluffy.
And we're done.
We made masa.
Every once in while
I get one of those OMG moments.
That right there --
that just hit a new level.
Next, we're gonna make
the tinga for the tamales.
The who?
The tinga for the tamales.
What is the tinga?
It's the filling that's gonna
go in the middle.
That's what you call it?
Tinga?
Yeah. That's what
I really call it.
So, tomatoes,
if you leave them alone
and let them burst,
and, so -- yes.
That's what
you're listening for.
we're looking for?
Yeah.
Just want to add
some onions and some garlic.
Get it roasted down.
All right.
So, we got that all cooked down.
And then we're gonna
transfer it into a blender.
We've got
some chipotle peppers.
Yep. With adobo.
Salt.
That's it. Blend it.
Just a little bit
'cause I like it to be
a little bit chunky.
You want some chunk.
Give it a little taste.
[ Sighs ]
That's a tinga.
Yeah.
Now, let's roll them.
Okay, then.
This is just baked
pulled chicken.
Put this on there and mix it
around a little bit.
Okay.
If you'll wring
those out for me.
Wring them?
Those are corn husks.
We soak them
in the warm water
just so they'll be
a little bit more pliable.
You take some masa.
And then
just one little mush.
Got it.
We've got the tinga here.
Put it in the middle
and roll it up.
I try not to be too wild
at making it perfect
because the steam
will fix that.
And then I like this little tuck
you do like that.
Tie it with a bow.
And then that's it.
How long are you
gonna steam these?
For about 20 minutes.
Tamales are ready.
Pull it out.
Hot tamale is great
when it's served
right out of the pot.
It's gonna be the best.
It's still steaming.
Now, do you do this
to everybody?
You open it all up?
Yeah. Yeah.
This is how you get it.
I put a little
tomatillo sauce on top.
And that's it.
It's ready to go.
[ Exhales ]
I'm not kidding you.
Look at that grin right there.
"Uh-huh. I know."
The tomatillo salsa --
spot on.
Coming together with the masa --
the super-light masa
with the whipped chicken fat.
I mean, that is fluffy,
tender...spicy.
This has got to be one of
the best I've ever had.
Okay.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
Wow.
These are great tamales.
Good, soft, tender.
The tomatillo sauce
is absolutely delicious.
Do you like eating here?
Yeah.
What do you like
about it?
Tacos, lemonade.
It's all about the food.
Bursting with flavor.
I'm eating the rest
of this damn thing.
I can tell you that right now.
It's too damn good.
[ Laughter ]
Off the hook.
This girl's dangerous.
Watch yourself
when you're in Nashville.
Up next on this hour-long
holiday celebration...
-This is a one-stop shop.
-...in Boynton Beach, Florida...
Cabbage bling.
...a Jewish bakery and deli.
-It's the real deal.
...where the whole family's
getting into the act.
You're a fantastic man.
You know, diners come
in every shape or size.
I think we've seen that
as we've toured the country
here on "Triple D." You know,
you get your free-standing
to the ones
that are in strip malls.
Well, today, I'm at a combo
joint, a diner-bakery-deli
here in Boynton Beach
in South Florida.
Now, it may be in South Florida,
but their roots come
from up north in New York City.
Time we check out Flakowitz.
MAN:
Pick up corned beef, please?
-So everybody loves it?
-Everybody loves it.
-This is the good stuff.
-A full-service deli...
-Double potato salad.
-...and bakery.
Their chocolate babka
is very good.
This is the only game in town.
Thanks to New York food biz vets
Robert Pirozzi...
Reuben to go!
...his dad, Angelo,
who does the baking...
-Bagels, the babka.
-...and Dominick Locastroh.
Knackwurst, double fries.
-Serving up all the classics.
-I always order the corned beef.
The bread to meat ratio...
Their matzo ball soup
is the bomb.
The food is just as good
as we get up north.
FIERI:
And the menu's just as big.
Brisket dinner up.
Seeded rye
with pastrami and corned beef.
The best Reuben I've ever had.
Mmm!
Not just the sandwiches,
but the bakery is awesome.
The rugelach are delicious.
[ Laughs ]
Breakfast, lunch, and dinner,
it's all good.
This is a one-stop shop.
You guys are making over 200
your-recipe items here.
From scratch.
Like Romanian steak
with mushroom and onions...
-Good flavor to it.
-...braised lamb shank...
-It's delicious.
-...and this classic.
The stuffed cabbage
is outstanding.
Stuffed with beef and rice
and topped
with sweet and sour sauce.
I see the cast of characters
are out here.
80/20 ground beef.
Some of the liquid chicken.
-Sauteed onions.
-I like that.
It looks like
they're almost caramelized.
Yeah, they are. Knead this
in here. Cooked rice.
Did a little chicken stock
in it?
Absolutely.
That's why I see a little bit
of yellow coming in.
Yes, sir.
Brown sugar.
That's the one that I think
surprises me the most.
It's got to be
a little sweet.
Salt.
A little white pepper.
So we got this
all mixed up.
We're gonna do our 4-ounce
scoops, right across.
-So we're done with that.
-I'm done with that guy.
Now, tell me the story about
what happened to the cabbage.
We actually stick it
in the freezer for a day.
Boil it after we freeze it.
Well, if you can't
get it tender that way,
then there's no way
to get it tender.
-We're gonna core this out.
-Look at that. Cabbage bling.
I use the outer leaves
to line the bottom of the pan
so it doesn't burn
when we cook it.
Lay a little base down.
Now, what's cabbage sauce?
Tomato puree,
carrots, celery, onions,
brown sugar,
red wine vinegar,
lemon juice,
two fresh lemons.
Gonna make a slurry.
With corn starch,
you tighten it up.
All right. So what we do now
is we get a leaf.
-Over.
-Just like this. Over.
-Tucked in.
Lay it down in.
There you go.
Little bit more sauce on top.
Cabbage, parchment paper.
Aluminum foil
so it keeps the steam in.
We serve it up, and do we put
a little cabbage sauce on that?
Cabbage sauce right on top.
-Are you okay?
-I'm starting to drool.
Looks good, huh?
Mmm.
Pretty good flavor.
"Pretty good flavor"?
Great flavor.
So I like mine
with a little of lemon.
Give it a little shot of lemon,
taste it.
[ Laughs ]
Without question!
You can't let it go out
without lemon on it.
Just kind of
brings it all together.
Package deal.
Cool, man. Really nice.
That cabbage is fantastic.
It's like a sweet and sour
taste. Very, very good.
-Big enough portion?
-Oh, boy.
Come here to eat.
-At least once or twice a week.
-You bet.
MAN:
Have the stuffed cabbage.
Everything you get here
is just great.
-It's the real deal.
So's this guy...
It's quite a busy shop.
...Angelo Pirozzi,
who's baking everything
from bagels to babkas.
We make about 30 varieties
of cookies.
And only on Friday,
his famous potato knish.
It's flaky and delicious.
Now we're gonna make
the knishes.
This is pre-boiled.
I'm gonna start chopping them
into little sections.
And we're leaving
the skins on.
Yes, that's very healthy.
Add the onions to it.
This is the white pepper,
garlic.
I call that vitamin G.
Yeah, okay.
And this is the salt.
All right. "Be quiet."
I heard you.
Now, this is the butter.
I'm not gonna put all of it in.
I'm gonna cube this up
a little bit.
I think we're
putting it all in.
We might as well.
Mix it all up.
What temperature is this gonna
be in the oven?
About 350.
We're gonna
put the potato mixture...
-Into the mixer.
-Right.
We put the sour cream in.
-By the handful.
-So, are we done now?
-Yeah, this is done.
-It mixed enough?
-One, two, three, then go.
Well, we have to do it together,
though.
Okay, all right.
One, two, three.
-Three.
-Go.
Go.
Okay, see?
Lucky I'm here today.
Yeah, I need you.
[ Laughs ]
I really felt the sincerity
in that one.
I'm gonna take one piece
of phyllo dough at a time,
coat it with butter,
fold it,
and then you're gonna put
a nice glob in there.
Did you say "glob"?
-[ Chuckles ]
-I like that.
Okay.
Let me jump in here.
All right. Should we
sign him up, or what?
What do you think?
Beautiful, Guy.
And then I wash it with eggs.
-So it gets a nice sheen.
-Right.
You put on egg wash
like I paint fence.
-It will go in the oven.
-For about 20 minutes.
We're gonna have trouble
eating all those.
Is there a method
of eating it, or...
Try it
with a little mustard.
Mmm. Delicious.
The phyllo dough is great.
-Uh-huh.
-It's light.
The potato is nice and hot.
You know what I like?
You left the skins on
and you roasted it,
so it kind of
gives some color.
Mmm. But you're right, buddy --
the mustard.
I haven't had
a lot of knishes,
but the one's I've had
do not compare to that.
Oh, thank you.
And the stuffing
is really excellent.
Nice. It's light, flaky.
Delicious.
Meatloaf's in the window.
I've never, never
had a bad meal.
-The food is great.
-Good job, fellas.
It's a big family operation,
though. It really is.
FIERI:
And everybody knows you.
-We're Flakowitz people.
-We love it here!
You did a very nice job on that.
Well, you did a good job.
I'm surprised
that you did it very well.
-I figured it out.
-Pleasure meeting you.
You're a fantastic man.
Coming up in Tennessee...
I don't even really know
what to say at this point.
...when it comes to the hog...
It's pretty ham.
...things are really heating up.
I have far too much
hair-care product
to be messing around
with a torch like that.
And in Long Beach,
California...
John, boy,
you know how to cook.
...a local cafe
putting their stamp on stuffing.
Whoa! Really good.
I'm in the great state
of Tennessee --
one of my favorites.
Why?
Well, home of Jack Daniels,
the Grand Ole Opry,
and some killer barbecue.
Now, I'm in Hendersonville,
about 10 miles from Nashville,
on the corner of Center Point
and Main Street
to check out a joint
that's got a ton of character
and a bunch of stories.
This is Center Point Barbecue.
Brisket. Corn on the cob.
Spicy red slaw.
The best barbecue in the south.
Pulled pork.
This is authentic
as you're gonna get.
Everybody loves their barbecue.
FIERI: 'Cause when it comes
to smoking meat,
owner Robert Duke
doesn't mess around.
You're the cleanest
pit master I know.
Well, I cleaned up for you.
This is my Sunday best.
And the smell coming
from his three smoke pits
is like a come-and-get-it bell
for the locals.
Generally, I think you can
smell it about a mile away.
Just makes your taste buds
want to drop by and eat it.
FIERI: Whether it's a full rack
of ribs, smoky beef brisket,
or one of Robert's down-home
family traditions.
Pulled pork.
This little restaurant's been
here since I was a little kid.
Some of my first memories here
with my dad
getting a barbecue sandwich.
I remember coming in here
as a little girl,
and it would be
wall-to-wall people.
FIERI:
Great barbecue, tons of history,
but I got to
tell you something.
There's one thing I have heard
about Center Point Barbecue,
and it is this sugar-glazed,
honey-smoked ham.
-Is it time?
-We're ready to do it.
-Bring on the brine.
-Let's do it.
We'll start off
with two gallons of water here.
Salt.
Sugar.
Equal parts salt and sugar.
Got you.
Cloves. Cinnamon.
Cinnamon-amon-amon.
Little pickling spice?
Just a little bit.
And then
white clove honey.
White clove honey.
How do you know?
-Says it on the bottle.
-Okay.
We're gonna bring this
to a boil.
Then let it cool down.
So, our ham trimmed up,
going in the brine.
How long are we gonna
let it brine?
We're gonna go four days.
Four days
it's gonna brine? Nice.
Does it go to the smoker?
Ready to go.
It's about six hours.
225. That's it.
It's pretty ham.
Next up?
Making the glaze.
Brown sugar.
Cloves.
Black pepper.
Sugar. Cinnamon.
Mix that together.
Get the moisture out of it,
put it in the shaker,
And we're ready to
glaze the ham then.
Okay.
Ready, Guy?
Hang on a second.
Let's warm this thing up
a little bit.
Now you're cooking
with gas!
Sugar
in the ham seasoning.
This is the ham seasoning.
I have far too much
hair-care product
to be messing around
with a torch like that.
[ Laughter ]
We got to let that rest.
Oh, you think?!
Yeah.
I don't even really know
what to say at this point.
I have seen some things
in my day.
That one, I'm gonna
need some therapy for.
Wow. It's hard
like an Easter egg.
Let's get into this.
[ Grunts ]
Was that a growl
you just made?
Mmm.
You haven't even had
any yet,
and you're grunting
and growling.
[ Grunts ]
That's all this love
down in here -- ah!
You guys got to see this.
Look at the bark.
Beautiful.
[ Grunts ]
Well, it's delicious.
I got to tell you something.
At certain parts of that,
almost like brittle.
Like ham brittle.
I'll tell you something -- every
once in awhile on "Triple D,"
you got to bring in authority
who really knows
what food tastes like.
Get over here, Ethan.
Watch yourself.
Got your gloves on?
Get over here, Coop.
Let's see what these two
little lunch faces think.
What do you think?
It's really good.
Is it really good?
Dude, give me a...
[ Mumbles ]
The good stuff!
There you go.
Hey!
Ham plate up, please.
The smoked ham is fantastic.
So wonderful
during the holidays.
It just is a delight
to my family table.
Outstanding, my friend.
So here I am
at one of my favorite cities
in the entire country --
Long Beach, California.
Now, I used to work
about a mile that way
at a place called Parker's
Lighthouse in Shoreline Village,
and I lived about 2 miles
that way in Belmont Shore.
Man, so many great memories!
But I love
rolling back into town
and checking out
some of my favorite joints,
kind of like Schooner or Later,
but also some of the new places
that have opened up,
like this place, At Last Cafe.
-Two pork chops, medium.
-The food is absolutely amazing.
-I have a brick chicken for you.
-Brick chicken. Delicious.
The mac and cheese is ready.
Oh, the macaroni and cheese
is excellent!
Gourmet cooking. This is
something very special.
FIERI: From former high-end chef
John McGlaughlin,
who decided great cooking
shouldn't cost a fortune.
Is this like a non-profit?
French pot roast, $10.50.
Brick chicken --
half a chicken -- $9.50.
-And for $10.25...
-Stuffed pork chops.
This is beyond good.
This is really awesome.
The gravy is amazing.
JOHN: We make our gravy
with chicken bones, tomato.
-Chicken bones and tomatoes.
-That's it.
Without any fuss and feathers.
JOHN: I just take chicken bones,
stick 'em in the oven,
roast 'em
till they're really brown.
An hour and a half,
something like that.
-All browned up.
-Then tomato.
Shoot it back in the oven,
brown that up a little bit.
Okay. Like the brown gravy
mad scientist.
When the tomatoes cook somewhat,
cold water to cover.
Pop it back in there.
So is it ready to strain now?
-Yeah.
-Oh. You got this?
-You might want to hold it.
-Oh, now hold it.
Wow. That is the craziest stock
I've ever seen.
-No herbs, no sweetness.
-That comes later.
Well, actually, we don't put
too much in it after, either.
What I normally do
is I refrigerate it,
then skim the grease
off of it
and add some red wine,
salt, and pepper.
-Thicken it with a slurry.
-Little corn starch.
Just let it come to a boil
and see what happens.
Way more flavor than
I anticipated. Now what?
We sauté apples and onions for
the stuffing for the pork chop.
Start out with
a little butter, oil, too.
Butter for flavor,
oil to cook.
Onions, apples.
-Granny Smith?
-Yep.
Nice, firm texture.
Salt and pepper,
and that's it.
Take that
and mix that into the bread
that we're gonna be putting for
the stuffing and the chop.
Yep.
Start with some rye bread.
Now the sauteed apples
and onions that we did.
-Some chopped parsley.
-Curly, not Italian.
Mixed dried herbs.
Dried cranberries.
So, currently, you're not
putting your currants in?
Currently not.
A little cinnamon,
a little salt.
Black pepper, one egg,
veggie stock.
Just mix it up just till
it kind of comes together.
-Okay, that's it.
-All right, grab the chop.
We're gonna lightly
marinate the chops.
Chopped garlic, some honey,
black pepper,
a little salt, soy sauce.
Some of my favorite
ingredients here.
-A little lemon juice.
-Little citrus.
Some olive oil
to dissolve the honey.
So, marinade is made.
Tell me about the chops.
They're already
lightly brined.
-From your butcher?
-Yes.
Okay, so we go ahead,
set 'em up.
Good looking glaze there.
How long will these marinate?
Two or three hours.
And then we'll
stuff them to order.
Yes.
I like it. Open wide.
This one's ready to go, then.
-Yeah.
-Let's cook it.
Olive oil.
I just brown it.
-Dig it.
-Salt and pepper.
Once I think it's brown,
I flip it
and then just go ahead
and throw it in the oven.
Finish it in the oven,
seven, eight minutes.
And what will this
be served with?
Mashed potatoes,
fresh vegetables,
our beautiful
homemade gravy.
-The magic gravy.
-All right.
Hmm. I tell you what,
John, boy, you know how to cook.
Chop is super tender.
The stuffing is just --
That's all the rave. The apples
and marinade on the outside
the garlic and the soy,
a little citrus.
-You tie it all together, man.
-Thank you.
-Way to go.
-Mm-hmm. Thank you very much.
Nice job.
[ Chuckles ] Really good.
Pork chop for you.
I have never had a pork chop
that was any more tender
and juicy and moist.
The gravy is wonderful, too.
It is delicious.
Moist, tender, very flavorful.
-Perfect.
-This is great. I love this.
So everything you've had here,
you've enjoyed?
Always.
Whatever you eat
is gonna taste really good.
-It's gonna be fresh.
-At the end of the day,
that's why you come back.
The food is fabulous.
We have a meatloaf
for you.
Pricing is important,
but even if it were more --
Oh, no!
I was gonna say --
Even it was more expensive?
[ Laughter ]
Don't worry.
-I won't tell him.
-No, I did not say that.
Did not say that.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
west to San Fran...
Wow.
...for an authentic taste
of the East...
I'm an east coast deli guy.
Every bit.
...including one more matzo
with its own family spin.
Do you have license
to matzo ball?
So, I'm here in beautiful
San Francisco, California.
Now, you've heard of
Fisherman's Wharf, right?
Okay, good,
'cause we're not going there.
We're going like 3/4 of
a mile south on Polk Street
to exactly what you'd expect
to find here in San Fran,
an East Coast deli.
This is Miller's.
I love
the corned-beef sandwich.
Get in on that. Come on.
Release the jaw.
Best pastrami I've ever had.
Big sandwich.
Like, bigger than my face.
I want to see a Guy Fieri bite
on this thing.
There you go!
The best deli
on the West Coast.
FIERI: 'Cause owner
Robby Morgenstein...
Could you get me
a pastrami Philly?
FIERI: ...comes from
a Baltimore bloodline
or blintzes and bagels.
My grandparents
were kosher caterers.
All of my cousins
have delis.
So when he started
this place in 2001,
his very loving mom handed over
all the family recipes,
including this deli classic...
I got the chicken-noodle soup
with matzo balls.
...that's been in Robby's family
for generations.
The matzo-ball soup
is delicious.
Matzo balls.
Do you have license
to matzo ball?
I got a grandmother
and a mother.
Okay.
God rest them.
Rose and Rae
made matzo balls.
Rose and Rae.
Fire up the chicken stock.
A little bit of olive oil.
Some mirepoix -- a couple
of big onions, celery, carrots.
A couple of big chickens.
Those are big. Those look like
San Francisco pigeons.
A big thing of parsley.
[ Whistles ]
A fistful
of peppercorns.
And some bay leaf.
A lot of water.
All right,
how long is this gonna go?
Come to a boil,
bring it down to a simmer --
about 90 minutes.
Strain it,
shred the chicken,
and while that's working,
we're going to --
Make some matzo balls.
Matzo meal, some salt,
a little bit
of white ground pepper.
You want to mix that up
real good.
That's all the dry.
Now you got all the wet.
So, for each cup of matzo meal,
you got four eggs.
1/4 cup of
schmaltz per cup.
So, what's the schmaltz
all about?
Schmaltz is flavored
chicken fat.
You're gonna
mix that together.
So, all the wet.
Look at this.
That's all she wrote.
So we let this set.
Then, after it forms up --
Just gonna take,
you know, an inch.
And how long
will they cook?
They're gonna cook
about 45 minutes.
A little bit of schmaltz.
Some mirepoix -- onions,
some carrots, some celery.
They're all nice
and sweated out.
We're gonna throw
the chicken stock on top
and then let it cook down
for about 30 minutes or so.
Now that's cooked down.
Now what?
Now we add fresh,
shredded chicken
from the stock
and then the matzo balls.
And then we get a little bit
of cooked egg noodles.
Let it get nice and hot.
And then we serve.
That's correct.
Word to the bird.
Ready?
Here we go.
One.
A little bit of stuff
on top.
[ Whistles ]
Boy, look at that.
Look how hearty that is.
Tender matzo balls.
That's the key right there.
Mmm.
Simple, to the point,
but I'll tell you something.
Out of the matzo balls
that I've had,
that is one tender, delicious,
flavorful matzo ball
with great chicken stock.
Well, thank you.
Matzo-ball soup.
Having been making matzo balls
for over 40 years myself,
this one's delicious.
MAN: I tell everybody
who's an East Coast transplant
they got to come here and try it
for themselves.
FIERI: 'Cause the menu's
chockful of East Coast flavors
with no West Coast compromise.
MAN #2: Everyone likes to
Californian-ize everything,
and Miller's is not California.
FIERI: Nothing's been lost
in translation,
whether it's the whitefish
platter,
the brisket french dip,
or this East Coast classic...
Potato Latke Delight.
...loaded with killer pastrami
and corned beef
that's shipped in from Detroit.
They're the best.
It's to die for.
So, a beautiful piece
of brisket here.
Pickled-corned-beef brisket.
And what are we gonna do
with it?
So, this puppy goes in.
And start it in some cold water
to cover.
We're just gonna simmer it off
for 3, 3 1/2 hours.
Some bay leaves,
a little bit of pickling spice.
A little more pickling spice.
No more salt.
It's already had the brine.
Cook this for 3 1/2 hours.
Transfer to the steam oven?
Yep.
All right, so, we're now
making the latkes.
A lot of
manufacturing potatoes,
all shredded up,
and a lot of eggs --
more than you would think.
And then a lot of onion.
Okay.
And then this is something
you got to do with your hands.
You get caught doing this
with your foot,
people are gonna tweak out.
That's probably true.
A little bit
of granulated garlic,
some onion powder, a good amount
of salt, black pepper,
and we're gonna mix
that up.
And then
just enough matzo meal.
If you put too much matzo meal
in, you got a puck of lead.
And that's it.
So, on the griddle.
[ German accent ]
On the griddle.
Now we scoop them out.
Nice big piles.
[ Normal voice ]
Cook them up on both sides?
You're gonna mark them
on both sides,
then we're gonna take them
to the deep fryer.
Show me the goods.
Pastrami.
Corned beef all cooked up,
ready to go.
We're just
gonna trim it up.
Grab your latkes.
Wow.
A couple of latkes.
Start on the point.
So, every time an order
comes out,
you're cutting it
to order?
We cut it to order.
How much do we give people?
A half-pounder?
Oh, easily.
This is more than that.
[ Whistles ]
And then the pastrami.
Get a nice pile of that.
Whoa!
A little bit of sour cream
and fresh applesauce.
Can I try this?
Go.
So, the proper method
of eating this
would be to --
You get a big chunk
of everything,
and then you dip it down
into the applesauce
and the sour cream.
Got it.
The latke is nice and crispy
but tender on the inside.
The corned beef is dynamite,
but the one that I really got
to try -- Wow.
That's some great pastrami.
That dude goes bananas.
Unh. Excellent job.
Thank you, man.
Really.
Dynamite.
Potato Latke Delight.
MAN: I'm never disappointed
with ordering it.
It's amazing.
MAN #2:
My mother makes good latkes,
but now Miller's latkes
are the standard.
Sorry, Mom.
I mean, here's the thing
I love about it.
It's using great product.
Scratch-making
the items you can,
and you have it
in a funky environment.
Feels like you're in
an East Coast deli.
I'm an East Coast deli guy.
Every bit.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry.
We've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Bowls clopping ]
[ Laughter ]