Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
-This trip...
-Whoa!
...it's time for
a little pick-me-up...
That is not for
the faint of heart.
...with righteous,
finger-licking food.
What are we gonna do
with this
besides just throw it
at my mouth?
We're talking a crazy
Minneapolis mash-up.
Filipino flair
on an English pub.
Dishing out the bomb bacon dip.
That is ridiculous.
And the big-time bánh mi.
That's the hinge point
of greatness.
Plus, a classic
Cape Cod seafood spot...
There's nothing wrong
with that.
...where the lobster
is cracking...
You got that right.
...and the mussels are money.
They just kind of start
melting in your mouth.
And a funkalicious brew house
in Atlanta...
It's got to be the crown jewel
of the area.
...re-inventing the corn dog.
You even get
souvenir sticks.
And pumping up the pastrami.
Dude, out of bounds.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
I'm in one of the famous parts
of Atlanta, Georgia,
known as Little Five Points.
I mean, all kinds of
great restaurants and bars,
good place to go and hang out.
Now, right around the corner
from that is Inman Park,
and that's one of the oldest
neighborhoods in the area
with all these really cool,
old, Victorian homes.
We're here to check out a joint
in one of those homes.
This is Wrecking Bar Brew Pub.
Crispy pig ears.
It's definitely unique.
It looks like a dungeon,
but in a really cool way.
FIERI: Pull up, and I see
the big old columns.
I'm, like, "Oh, boy,
this ain't a Triple D."
But then you drive
around the back,
and that's when you come
down here into Funkytown.
Going down
in the rabbit hole.
FIERI:
And what you find,
well, is courtesy of
Steven Rosslow and his partners,
who transformed
this down-and-out mansion
into a brew pub in 2011.
So, what was it
when you got it?
-I mean, like, boarded up
and the whole thing?
-Yeah.
You come up with
the genius idea
that you can take the basement
and the back building
-and put a brewery in it.
-Perfect fit.
About as perfect
as putting chef Terry Koval
in charge of the kitchen.
It's not bar food,
you know.
It's the next level.
Beef heart tartare
in the window.
MAN: Local pork, local beef,
local chicken, local fish,
even the cornmeal
on the corn pups
is coming from a local farmer.
Corn pups for you.
It's really kind of
a step above a corn dog.
Probably one of my favorite
items on the menu.
Really cheesy, super good.
What do we do
with this whole hog?
KOVAL: We're making
the cheddarwurst sausage.
Take out the shoulder.
We're gonna break this thing
down, grind it, and add salt.
Pepper.
Chili flake,
Colman's Mustard,
curing salt,
Vermont white cheddar.
-And that's it?
-Yeah.
All right, we're gonna stuff
some sausage here.
Okay, ready?
All right, let's do this.
Take it off.
We're gonna tie it off.
-Poke it.
-Yep.
All right, now we're gonna
torque this thing.
Watch out.
-Whoa, hey, ho.
-[ Laughs ]
You got to get
this thing tight, you know.
I bet you do.
Get right after that.
We're gonna hang it,
let it dry for 12 hours.
Then we'll go to the smoker.
-How long is it in the smoker?
-40 minutes.
What kind of wood
we smoking with?
-Oak and hickory.
-Okay.
Now we're gonna slice it.
Cut off the ends.
Take off that casing,
then slice our little disks.
-Dip.
-And what's in the batter?
Cornmeal, got some buttermilk,
a little flour, that's it.
I can already tell
these are not going to suck.
Just a little charcuterie plate
with this.
Yeah.
That Vermont cheddar in there,
touch of smoke.
Mmm!
Get all over that.
Let's fry these.
Great ketchup, French's mustard,
little kid style.
Little kid style.
Delicious, man.
-Thank you.
-Mm.
Nice spice,
right amount of cheese.
You can taste the pork.
I don't think
I would have ever thought
curry ketchup
to go with it, spot on.
Look at that.
And you even get
souvenir sticks.
Chef, well done.
The flavoring of the meat inside
was just phenomenal.
Bite into it, it's like cheese
that oozes out of it.
WOMAN:
It's fun to come and eat here
because there's no other place
like it that I've eaten.
20 years ago, this was not
a safe neighborhood.
MAN:
It was a pretty building,
but obviously, like,
had fencing around it,
had graffiti on it.
WOMAN:
I love that they came in,
and they brought it back
to its glory.
Down here at the pub,
they scratch make everything.
Well, that's the best part
about here.
They make
all their pastrami in house.
They cure it all here.
Pastrami and a slaw.
Call my mommy.
It's time for pastrami.
So, we're gonna do a brine
for our pastrami.
Okay, we're gonna go
water in.
Sugar.
-Salt.
-Okay.
Garlic.
We got
our pickling spice here.
This is the house
pickling spice.
Yeah.
And last but not least...
Pink salt here.
Brings out that nice ruby-red
color that we like. Okay.
Dissolve all this sugar
and all this salt.
And then drop the brisket.
Word.
Mixture is cooled.
It looks like tea.
Look at that.
How long we gonna brine it?
-Four days.
-Okay.
All right,
so we got our rub here.
We got ground coriander,
some fresh cracked black pepper.
Nice Vanna White pour,
by the way.
Lovely brown sugar.
You see the way
he popped and posed?
Granulated garlic.
Make it rain up in here.
Whew.
[ Laughs ]
Granulated onion.
Got some smoked paprika.
Dry mustard.
And we got
a little kosher salt.
Mix this up.
It's like you're looking
for a ring or something.
Nothing in there, son.
-All right, we're good.
-Okay.
So, we're gonna rub
these things down.
There we go,
let's dry that thing down.
All right, perfect.
Now, are we gonna
let this sit
with the dry rub
for a little bit,
or is it just gonna go
right to the smoker?
It's gonna go right
in the smoker.
-Hickory and oak, 11 hours.
-Yep.
225, then I eat it all.
Now we're getting into this.
Oh, that
doesn't look terrible.
Slice away.
Oh!
The pastrami bark on that
is out of bounds.
What are we gonna do
with this
besides just throw it
at my mouth?
[ Laughs ]
Mmm, right amount of smoke.
I mean, that is legit.
So, we're gonna make
our pastrami sandwich.
We got our marble rye down,
some baby Swiss.
Baby it up.
Melt the cheese, steam
this pastrami a little bit.
Cheese is good.
You sure?
Yeah, add our
baby collard kimchi.
And we got our chili mayo.
Fantastic, man.
That is not for
the faint of heart.
Everybody's playing nice
with each other,
and then all of a sudden,
someone invited the kimchi.
It's kicking and screaming
inside that sandwich right now.
[ Laughs ]
Pastrami's trying
to hold onto
its starting quarterback
position.
Want to have a food fight
in your mouth?
Order that thing.
Nicely done.
WOMAN: Probably one
of the best sandwiches
I've eaten in my life.
FIERI: It's like
pastrami gone wild.
I should buy a DVD box set
of that pastrami.
I know. [ Laughs ]
The food is very flavorful
and very different.
It's been popular since Day 1.
It's really good.
FIERI: Crazy joint.
It's got to be the crown jewel
of the area.
It's a dream come true.
-Nice job.
-Thanks.
-Coming up in Minneapolis.
-Awesome place.
An English pub
with killer grub....
You know what?
This should be illegal.
...mixing in some
Filipino flavor?
Isn't that the kicker?
So, I'm here
in southwest Minneapolis
on a beautiful, sunny
Minnesota day.
So, when I say the name to you,
Green Mesquite,
what kind of restaurant
you thinking of?
Exactly, barbecue.
I say Over Easy,
you think breakfast.
I say Zydeco, you think,
it's got to be Cajun.
So, what do you call a joint
that is an English pub
with a little Filipino flair?
You're right,
this is George & and the Dragon.
Got a merry salad in the window.
Something different and unique,
yet down to earth
and in the neighborhood.
STACY:
Battered green beans.
This is like the Cheers
of south Minneapolis.
Got an Asian hangover.
Filipino flair
on an English pub.
-Yeah.
-Something you hear every day.
FIERI:
Every day here since 2011
when this joint was opened
by the Navarro family --
Fred, Stacy, and Paco.
They say,
"What kind of food is that?"
And you say it's...
Well, it is home cooking,
pretty much.
The kind of cooking that happens
when fans of British culture mix
it up with old family recipes.
My family
is from Minnesota.
-Heritage is French and Irish.
-Okay.
And both my parents were born
and raised in the Philippines.
Got a curry in the window.
It's not just bar food.
It's dinner food.
It's brunch food.
Delicious food, that's for sure.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
The bacon dip.
Bacon onion dip.
It's one of those dishes you can
have as a starter or a meal.
All right, so let's talk about
this first dish.
So, we'll make onion jam
which is gonna go
into the bacon and onion dip.
A little house oil
in the pan.
It's a blend of corn oil
and olive oil.
And then we add in
sliced onions.
Sweat these down?
Yep, till they get nice
and soft.
A little sprinkle of salt.
We're gonna sprinkle them over
with some brown sugar.
Does anybody tell you
that you have
the voice and the calm demeanor
of Barefoot Contessa?
-[ Laughs ]
-"The next,
I'll be adding the..."
Little balsamic vinegar.
And let me give it
a little bit of water.
We let it simmer for
about 30 to 40 minutes
until all the moisture
is absorbed.
-Okay.
-And then we cool them down.
So, we've got the cooled,
caramelized onions.
Where's the bacon?
Sorry, man.
Bacon is coming.
So, we start
with cream cheese.
We're gonna whip this
until it's nice and fluffy.
We're gonna add our mayonnaise,
our Worcestershire sauce,
a little salt, cayenne pepper,
Colman's dry mustard,
Parmesan cheese.
And then
the caramelized onions?
the caramelized onions.
When is the bacon gonna be
coming into this?
-Sorry.
-I'm calling Paco.
I want
to talk to my union rep.
You want to talk
to the emperor?
Let this mix up.
And this is
a big-time favorite?
Big-time favorite.
So, we're gonna scoop it.
Top it off with Parmesan cheese,
and we're gonna put --
Wait, we're gonna put
bacon on it.
Cooked, cold bacon goes
on top in the oven.
We're gonna bake it at 350
for about 5 minutes.
This thing is coming out to
the table el smoldering hotto.
And we're gonna finish it off
with some chives.
Ooh, this is
like cheddar dippish.
That is ridiculous.
You know what?
This should be illegal.
It's not just onions
and bacon.
There's much more depth.
I think you know what really
makes it is that mustard.
A little tang of that,
it's better than good.
-Excellent, nice job.
-Cool. Thank you.
Bacon onion dip.
GIRL:
You got the creamy cheese,
the crunchy bacon.
You can't make it exactly like
you can at George & the Dragon.
-Meet your new host.
-[ Laughs ]
Got a bacon onion dip.
It's one of those things
that keeps you coming back.
FIERI: Bring the whole family
down while you're at it.
WOMAN:
Kids love coming here.
-Really?
-Yeah, Paco's book shelf
over there.
Tell me about
the book shelf?
My elementary school
had this competition
to see which class
could read the most minutes,
and I kind of wanted
to build a bookcase
to help other people
who are probably gonna come in.
If you're waiting for your food,
you can just
grab your book and read.
FIERI: Whether you're waiting
for classic British pub grub...
Certainly expect fish and chips,
which they do phenomenally here.
FIERI: ...or something from
the Asian side of the family.
Got the bánh mi
for you, ma'am.
Bánh mi sandwich is pretty
delicious, as well.
Okay, so let's get into it.
What are we making?
So, we start with
a whole pork shoulder.
We're just gonna trim some
of the fat off of here,
break this down
into smaller pieces.
And what's
gonna happen here?
I'm gonna rub it
with Chinese five spice.
It has fennel, star anise,
black pepper, and kosher salt.
Super fragrant.
And then we're gonna go
in the hot pan, sear it up.
Yep, and then
once this is browned,
we're gonna pull it off.
We're gonna add in onions, do
a little bit of garlic, ginger.
Hoisin sauce,
and then a little hot sauce.
And some soy sauce.
And then a little chicken stock.
So, the braising liquid
comes out on top of the pork.
Exactly.
In the oven, what temp?
-350 for about 2 to 3 hours.
-Next up?
We shred the daikon
and the carrot,
and then we are just
going to sprinkle it
with a little sugar,
a little salt.
Mix this through
until it kind of
begins to soften up
a little bit.
Sweat some
of the moisture out.
Exactly, and then
we go the cider vinegar.
We'll add sugar
and some hot water.
To help dissolve it.
How long will
we let this pickle?
48 hours.
So, that pork that
we put in the oven, it is ready.
-So, you can see now it's nice
and fall apart tender.
-Mm-hmm.
A little wasabi mayo
to put on the bun.
Both sides.
And then we're gonna
put the pork on there.
Look at that jus
going on there, whoa.
And then the pickled carrot
and some green beans.
Green beans, of all things.
And then there we go.
Mm!
That pork has more flavor
than the average bánh mi
by a long shot.
The wasabi mayo is kicking.
Perfect bread,
nice and light.
And then you get
a nice little vinegar kick
and then the great crunch
of the green bean.
That's the hinge point of
greatness, outstanding.
The bánh mi.
It is always juicy,
and it's always tender.
I was blown away
with that sandwich.
The texture
of the green beans is amazing.
Isn't that the kicker?
We love this place
because it's consistently good.
FIERI:
Cool English pub attitude,
a sixth grade emperor.
And a funky name,
we have it all going on.
Awesome place.
Up next in Woods Hole,
Massachusetts...
-The man, the myth,
the character.
...flavorful fresh catch...
The fish that we buy today swam
in the bay yesterday.
Don't you say?
...with personality
backing it up.
Isn't that beautiful, huh?
So, I'm here in Woods Hole.
It's one of the villages here
in Thalmus, Massachusetts,
in Cape Cod.
Thank you very much
for the ride, captain
Aarrgghh!
Now, this area is known
for a lot of things,
and for most folks, this is
where you catch the ferry
to go over to Martha's Vineyard.
But there's
a more important one,
and that is a little funky joint
with a self-proclaimed
world-famous attitude.
That's right, this is Shuckers
World Famous Raw Bar & Café.
I need to get this order
outta here!
The fish is fresh. It comes from
the local waters in Cape Cod.
You wouldn't really know
it's here
unless you walk down
that alley.
The people that work here,
we've known for years.
Big stuffed lobster.
We love Murph and Karen.
They're just wonderful people.
FIERI: Murph's a character,
also known as Murph-quake,
or Chef Kevin Murphy.
He and his wife, Karen, opened
this harbor hideaway in 1981
and have been dishes out clams,
oysters, and lobsters
to locals and tourists
ever since.
Folks love it here.
It's part of their vacation.
Every year,
they'll stop on the way
or on their way back
from Martha's Vineyard.
FIERI: How many of these
do you cook in a day?
50 to 100, it depends.
And if your main meal
isn't a whole lobster,
well, it's more than
likely there's lobster
in there somewhere.
I have
a baked stuffed scrod.
It's the best.
The fish is flaky yet firm,
a very nice sauce.
The dish we're gonna make
will be our stuffed cod.
Cod scrod.
Remember the word "scrod"
is really not a species of fish.
It's the size of the fish.
So, you're saying when it's
smaller, it's a scrod.
It's a scrod.
So, let's take these in,
and then we'll pick the meat.
Sounds good.
You got that right.
We really just rip off
the tails.
You just crack it
with your hand.
A lot of people cut
the shell with their --
When you're doing as much
lobster as we are, you can't --
We don't have time.
We don't got time to do
that kind of stuff.
The shenanigans.
We're gonna chop it up
a little bit.
Cracker crumbs.
Some pepper, paprika,
and melted butter.
All right,
so we've got that mixed.
I'm gonna cut
a piece of fish for you.
We buy native cod.
There is nothing fresher
than the fish when we buy today
because it swam
in the bay yesterday.
Don't you say?
What we're gonna do is,
we're gonna take a little bit
of the thicker end,
and I'm gonna that nice lobster
stuffing we just made
and put it on top of the cod.
How long?
Okay, so that's gonna go
12 to 15 minutes.
Now we're making?
We're gonna make
a beurre blanc sauce here.
Put some butter in the pan.
Put the shallots in there,
Sauvignon Blanc wine.
And what's this?
That's a little
simple syrup.
-Ooh.
-Add some sweetness to it.
Takes the bite
out of the shallots.
Got it.
Then the next thing
I have here
is a mixture of butter
and cream.
We're gonna
let that reduce down.
It's gonna take maybe 15 to
20 minutes at medium heat.
We have the garnish.
Scalloped potatoes?
Au gratin, not scalloped.
Au gratin, buddy.
-Come on.
-Au gratin.
Look at this beauty
here, huh?
We're gonna take
that beurre blanc sauce,
and we want to ladle a good bit
over the fish.
We're gonna garnish it
with a little dill weed,
a little lemon.
We're ready.
This is the real Cape Cod thing.
It tastes bright and fresh
and like the sea.
Nice and flaky and light.
Great seafood flavor.
The beurre blanc is dynamite.
Nice amount of wine in that.
Chef, nice job.
Thank you very much,
appreciate it.
-I'm telling you.
-I like it.
Murph-quake!
Hello, we have
the baked stuffed scrod.
Delicious.
The fish is tender and sweet.
I taste a little lemon.
Perfecto.
The right amount of lobster,
fresh fish, incredible sauce.
Hello, I have
your lobster boil for you.
The quality and quantity
of the food is first class.
FIERI:
But it's not just the bomb food
bringing customers back.
You want the seafood
in the right environment.
MAN:
You're right on the water.
Actually, we're floating
as we speak.
Love pulling up right here
for a nice, quaint lunch.
All right,
so here's the deal.
Not that I need to have
anything else to eat.
When we come back,
we're doing some mussels.
Sweet and tender.
They're good to the last drop.
-And they're off the hook?
-Off the hook.
Says it all the time.
See you in a bit.
All right.
Welcome back.
We're hanging out in Woods Hole.
Yep, that's right, here in
Thalmus, Massachusetts.
We are right in the area
where you jump a ferry
to go over
to Martha's Vineyard.
So, when you're waiting
for the ferry,
you're looking for
a place to come to.
You end up here at Shuckers
World Famous Raw Bar &...
Café!
-There you go.
-You got it, buddy.
My brother, Murph,
here has walked us through.
We did a fantastic
lobster-stuffed scrod.
Now we're into some mussels.
Portuguese mussels for you.
I'm Portuguese,
and the Portuguese mussels here
are the best.
Portuguese mussels have
the chorizo and the peppers.
The sauce is delicious.
Give me the rundown,
brother.
First thing, we're gonna take
the beards off of the mussels.
See that right there?
That's how the mussels
attach to the lines,
to the docks, to the rocks.
So you're gonna take
all the beards.
Yeah. Maybe somebody didn't
do that to you today.
Hey, watch yourself.
Watch yourself.
We're gonna take some butter.
Chorizo, ground up,
put it in there.
Okay.
Smell that.
Isn't that beautiful?
Isn't that beautiful, huh?
So, we're gonna take
some peppers and onions,
put 'em in there.
Now, the next thing we're gonna
add is a little Riesling wine.
It goes very well
with shellfish.
We're gonna put in
the mussels, okay?
-That's a lot of mussels.
-Yeah.
Three to four minutes,
and we got game time.
Soon as they open,
we're ready to roll.
That broth -- ooh, that's part
of the show right there.
Does that taste good.
I got to put out
the garlic bread.
I'm gonna throw that on.
So, you get it
right down in there,
throw a little
of that chorizo on top.
-What do you think?
-Mmm.
-Huh?
-Tender.
Has some flavor, too, huh?
Buttery, not overly salty.
Super tender.
I mean,
like, tender tender.
They just kind of start
melting in your mouth.
"A," that's a ridiculous amount
of mussels,
but "B," and most importantly,
outstanding.
They have a little kick to 'em.
And they kind of explode
in your mouth.
Right amount of garlic,
right amount of acid.
Love dipping the garlic bread
in the sauce.
-There's nothing wrong
with that.
-No.
This is what you look for when
you come to a Cape Cod place.
So, even though you are right in
the heart of a tourist area,
you are doing it legit,
keep paying respects to how
the seafood should be treated.
-That's the whole deal.
-You're exactly right.
The seafood
is the star of the show.
-You got that straight.
-Excellent.
Thank you so much.
Appreciate it.
The man, the myth,
the character.
So, that's it for
this trip, but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
-What makes good food?
-Flavor.
You have the put the right thing
so it has the right taste.
How did you learn all that?
I watch the show a lot,
and I learned
from the best, you.
[ Laughter ]