Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Primetime, dude.
...we're going big
with the pig...
What?
...putting out a plethora
of pork.
Makes your tongue go wild.
In Colorado Springs...
Oh, my gosh.
...a funky food truck...
That has got it going on.
...going global
with their meaty fusion.
I know that we're in Colorado,
but it sure feels like Miami.
In Minneapolis...
Get it, brother.
...a neighborhood brewpub...
There you go.
That's right.
...getting serious
with the smoke.
Just trying to pace myself and
not shove the entire sandwich
in my mouth at one time.
Plus, a righteous
ramen joint...
Is slurping appropriate?
...with plenty of flavor
to savor.
If they made this
in the 50-gallon drum,
I'd be having a hot tub
in it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in
Colorado Springs, Colorado,
and I'm looking for a food truck
that says they do pork fusion,
and they got
a really weird name, too.
It's Ig-pay Atin-lay,
or in Pig Latin,
that would be -- Pig Latin?
♪♪
Kalua sandwich!
All of these flavors just, like,
dance on your palate.
Island fries.
I fell in love
from the first time.
Pancetta
quesadilla's ready.
It's the most, like, tender pork
I've ever had.
FIERI: Courtesy of
husband-and-wife team
Andre and Tricia Velez,
whose road to food-truck glory
got detoured early on.
We were trying to get on
"The Great Food Truck Race"
when they were casting
for people that didn't
have food trucks.
We never ended up
getting on the show,
but then we had all
the planning, so we figured,
"Hey, let's just start a truck
anyway," you know?
Now they're owning it
on a daily basis.
Piggy grilled cheese.
How do you
describe the food?
Well,
it's called pork fusion.
Anything that works good
with pork.
Like this Colombian dish
Andre ate as a kid.
TRICIA: Stacked arepa.
Yeah, stacked arepa has sweet
and tender pork,
and it has the kick
of the Sriracha.
It's amazing.
What are we gonna make?
All right, here we're
gonna make sofrito
for the pineapple pork
that's gonna go in the arepa.
Hit it.
All right.
Mexican oregano.
Some ground cumin.
Salt and pepper.
Garlic cloves.
Onions.
Just regular yellow onion?
Roma tomatoes.
So that's gonna go in there
for a little bit.
[ Whirring ]
All right. I'll put the rest
of the Roma tomatoes.
Bell peppers.
And cilantro.
I wouldn't get
a bigger blender.
[ Laughs ]
I would keep that one.
There we go.
All this gonna go over
the pork butt?
Yes.
Look at that.
And to top it off,
we're going to put pineapple,
and then last,
brown sugar.
Go in the roaster
eight hours.
And what's all this gonna be
served on?
It's gonna be served
on an arepa.
You've got the masa right here.
Pour it in there.
Water.
Is this the same masa as masa
harina for tortillas?
Um, it's Colombian masa.
Colombian masa.
So it looks like it has
a little more grit to it,
a little more grain.
Put it on the arepa press.
Press it a little bit.
There we go.
In the fryer.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it.
All right.
Throw the mozzarella cheese
on this arepa right here.
Then we cover it.
So when anybody comes
to work for you,
they have to be, like,
do you have to measure them
to see if they
can fit in here?
Close quarters.
It's close quarters.
Yeah, if you're too big,
you're not coming in.
[ Sizzling ]
That's a little fat.
Get it going.
Spinach, we wilt it down.
And this is all for one?
One person.
Top it off with some of that.
And four plantains.
Some Sriracha right here.
Little cheese.
Yeah.
Some cilantro right here.
A little lime.
I actually forgot how much
I love arepa.
That's tasty, man.
What I like is the little crust
on the bottom,
when you got
to the flat top.
A lot of times
you don't find that.
You just get it right out
of the fryer.
Mozzarella cheese, as much as
it's not Colombian,
there's a nice stringiness
to it.
Mmm.
And that sofrito really works
with that pork.
Mmm. Great flavor.
Nice and tender.
Primetime, dude.
Primetime.
Appreciate it, Guy.
Perfectly crunchy,
but a very soft inside.
You can't go wrong with choosing
any of their selections.
Cheesy ham risotto balls!
I like this place
because it's a mixture
of a bunch of different places.
FIERI:
Which goes over big
in a city with four
military bases.
With people being stationed
all over the world,
they get different flavors,
and to see it all come together
in one plate,
it's really amazing.
FIERI: And Andre's serving
six years as an Army cook,
well, that doesn't hurt either.
I know that I'm supporting
a veteran,
and that's a great feeling
to have.
Pig Latin plate.
That plate is just phenomenal.
There's beans, rice,
and then plantains.
The pork's tender.
It works really well together.
All right,
what are we getting to now?
All right, here we're going
to be doing the mojo
for the Pig Latin Plate.
Okay.
First, it starts off
with orange juice.
Salt and pepper.
Some garlic.
A lot of garlic.
Oregano. Cumin.
Olive oil.
And then some lime juice
to give it a little sour kick.
All right, so we're getting
the pork butt.
Put some holes
in it first.
Then the mojo marinade.
A little oregano.
Cumin. And black pepper.
So it is pork again.
It is done in a Latin style,
but a completely different
direction.
Cover it up.
325 for 8 hours.
We ready to do this?
It's ready to go.
Let's do it.
Look at that.
Just pulls apart.
Nice crust on it.
That will work.
We're gonna get some rice.
We got some beans.
We got some tomato base,
cumin, oregano, sazón.
Not Vidal "Sazón."
Gooey plantains for you.
Pile of meat.
Top it off with cheese.
A little cotija?
Some cilantro right here
and a lime wedge
on top of the meat.
Do what you do.
Mmm. The mojo pork
is righteous, dude.
Oh, my gosh.
That has got it going on.
The beans, it's like they've
been cooked down for days.
Nice little bit
with the rice.
And then the mojo
on the pork.
There you go.
Now, I know that
we're in Colorado,
but it sure feels
like Miami.
Pig Latin Plate!
It's a little bit sweet,
a little bit salty.
It's perfect.
Island fries!
I love the Pig Latin Truck.
They pit a lot of love into it.
♪♪
I love the name.
The food's spot-on.
You guys are setting it up.
Nice job.
FIERI: Coming up in
a Minneapolis supermarket...
I like the way
this is going.
...a real-deal hidden gem...
It gets more wicked
with every bite.
...going way beyond
the store shelves.
You're wowing people, man.
This is --
this is "wow" food.
♪♪
No, this is not an episode
of "Guy's Grocery Games."
This is "Triple D."
I'm here in Minneapolis,
Minnesota,
in one of their largest
Asian grocery stores
to check out a funky little
ramen-noodle joint.
This is Unideli.
MAN: Kimchi ramen.
MAN #2: It's actually hidden
in a giant warehouse.
When you find it,
it's this oasis of awesome
food and flavor.
Have the Korean
chicken wings.
WOMAN: If you want an an
authentic Asian food experience,
this is the perfect place
to come.
FIERI: Which was grocery
only until Eric Fung's mom
bought the place in 2004
and added a deli.
Food has always been
a passion of ours.
It's just something that's
always close to my heart.
So in 2011, Eric jumped
into the family biz
and took the deli
to a whole new level.
There's a great menu.
There's so many different
things to try.
FIERI:
With chef Dan Prentice
throwing in the Asian cooking
skills he learned from his mom.
I grew up on amazing
Thai cooking.
So you "Thai'ed"
a lot of her food?
Yeah. Yeah,
I "Thai" it and I like it.
Dramen.
I am having the Dramen.
It's kind of like a Frankenstein
of ramen.
It is an amazing blend
of pork belly
with all of these Asian spices,
and then it's topped off
with the toasted sesame oil.
All right, so what are we making
first for the Dramen?
We're gonna start off with
this slab of pork belly,
and get it rolled up here.
Okay.
Oh, that's where I left
that thread
from my sewing machine.
We're gonna tie it off
with this?
Yep.
Next?
We're gonna hit it
with a little sugar.
A lot of sugar, actually.
Toss that one
in there for me.
That's a little sake.
And?
Soy.
Water?
Yep.
Fantastic.
Now we're gonna cover this up.
How long is this
gonna marinate?
Overnight.
Okay.
Then we pop it in the oven.
450 for an hour.
Got it.
And 250 for 2½ hours.
All right. Let's get into it.
What are we doing now?
Tsukemen.
Condensed chicken broth.
What's in there?
Chicken backs, chicken feet,
chicken wing tips.
You know, I just really often
enjoy a good chicken foot.
We already strained
this off.
Some miso paste?
Sake.
Got it.
Sugar.
Okay.
And bonito flakes?
Yep.
And the kombu.
Kombu is dried seaweed.
So think of the kelp
coming up like this.
We just dried it out and drove
over it with a steamroller.
In they go.
You took
the fun stuff away.
Give it a good stir.
We're just gonna let this simmer
a few more minutes,
get everything
mixed together,
and it's ready to serve
on the line.
♪♪
So, we've got a cross
between a miso soup --
"miso" hungry
and "miso" stupid.
Is this the key broth
for the Dramen?
No, the main broth we use
is a pork broth.
This is chicken on pig?
Yep.
All right, next one.
This is called
Tantanmen tare.
It's a spicy sesame paste.
Chili oil.
Okay.
Minced garlic.
Got it.
Ginger.
Sambal chili paste.
Got it.
We got the
sesame paste here.
Whoa!
We'll get
these fried onions.
Fried garlic.
I like the way
this is going.
Sake. Vinegar.
Tamari soy.
Got it.
Water?
Yep.
Some more of that kombu.
Float that right in there
with the 9,000 other
ingredients.
Salt. And sugar.
Whoa, right to the rim.
How long is
this gonna cook?
Half hour to an hour.
Okay.
All right, now let's put
this thing together.
Sliced up,
ready to torch.
Hit it with some mirin.
And just put a little
crust on it.
Mm-hmm.
See the drool come out
of my mouth just then?
Nice color to it.
And we'll strain some of
our pork broth into a bowl.
That's that.
Okay.
Now we go chicken stock.
And then the tare.
Yep.
Grab the noodles.
And we're gonna add a scoop
of the Tantanmen paste.
Couple greens.
Yu choy.
It's similar to bok choy,
Chinese broccoli.
Caramelized onions here.
Japanese pickled bamboo.
No egg?
No, I'm driving.
I'm trying to cut down.
And hit it
with this pork belly.
A couple peanuts.
Korean chili flakes.
Black and white sesame.
More chili oil.
Okay.
All this for one dish.
Yep.
Black garlic oil.
A couple leeks
on top there.
There you go, sir.
Mmm!
It gets more wicked
with every bite.
Wow. Outrageous.
This is brothy and rich
and deep.
There's not a lot
of fat in it,
but it has that real
coating-the-mouth feel to it.
That funky garlic oil
coming through.
The pork belly's
outrageous.
Is slurping appropriate,
or...
I think that's
the proper way to do it.
[ Slurping ]
If they made this
in the 50-gallon drum,
I'd be having
a hot tub in it.
The broth is perfect.
It's super savory.
It's spicy.
Not your college ramen.
It's a really,
really filling dish.
FIERI:
If you think Dramen is loaded
with tons of ingredients,
then you got to check out
the grocery store.
We have 9,000 products.
I don't know
how you keep track
of everything that you have
in here.
I've probably shoplifted
50 or 60 items.
The Camaro is full right now.
It's actually dragging.
MAN: I've always seen it
as kind of a hidden gem.
It's very, very awesome.
All right,
so here's the deal.
I'm hanging out
in a grocery store
that you will really have
to drive around
for a while to find.
But when you do,
you will come into Unideli
and try some fantastic ramen,
but that's not it.
We have another thing
coming up.
Don't tell 'em.
Barbecued pork.
It literally
tastes like candy.
I'm gonna take a small --
just a brief nap.
Enjoy the commercials.
♪♪
FIERI:
Here in Minneapolis,
we're inside the United Noodles
supermarket at Unideli,
which is way more than a deli.
It's a full-blown
Asian restaurant.
It's a little off
the beaten path,
but it's a hidden treasure.
FIERI: I've already
devoured the ramen,
taken a nap, and now we're going
way beyond the noodle bowl.
Barbecued pork.
Sweet, melts in your mouth.
It's very tender.
It's a very unique flavor
you can't have anywhere else.
Now what are we into?
Barbecue pork spice rub.
And this is going on pork loin,
pork shoulder, pork...
Pork shoulder.
All right.
"Cinnamoniminimanim."
Ginger.
Got it.
Fennel.
A little bit
of star anise here.
Okay.
Sichuan peppercorn.
Oh!
Makes your tongue go wild.
Ground cloves.
Okay.
And your salt.
So, pork shoulder all cut
and trimmed.
Yep.
We're gonna drop it
in the spice rub.
Now, how long is this gonna sit
in the dry rub?
Overnight.
Okay.
Next, the barbecue sauce?
Barbecue sauce.
Hoisin.
That's kind of like
the basis
of a lot of barbecue sauces
in Asian food.
Yeah, it's, you know,
called Chinese ketchup.
American ketchup.
Okay.
Mirin.
Bean sauce.
Got it.
Sugar.
Of course.
Garlic powder.
Granulated garlic.
Got it.
Liquid maltose.
Makes it a little sweeter,
a little fruity.
Give it a good stir.
Okay, so that's gonna get coated
on the outside of the pork.
Let it rest overnight.
Got it.
All right,
so we got it marinated,
and then how are we
gonna cook it?
We're gonna put it in
our stand-up oven here.
Whoa!
That's awesome.
This is getting medieval
on it.
Right through it?
Yeah.
Run this at 350.
Yep.
How long is
this gonna go?
Two hours.
How many of these
do you make a week?
Fresh every day.
Oh.
I wouldn't disrespect this
with a fork and knife.
It's tender.
It's juicy.
A little stickiness to that
barbecue sauce on the outside.
It's dynamite. I see why you
sell it by the pound.
Nice job.
Excellent job, Chef.
There's an amazing glaze on it.
It's extremely tender.
WOMAN: You get this really,
like, succulent pork
that tastes super sweet.
MAN: It's one of those dishes
you can usually share,
but I usually eat it all
by myself.
WOMAN #2:
Here's the Katsudon.
WOMAN #3: I promise you,
if you come to Unideli,
you will be addicted, and you
will never want to leave.
I just love
the whole attitude here.
Quick service, scratch-made,
and you're wowing people, man.
This is "wow" food.
Delicious.
Great job.
Glad you made it.
FIERI: Up next,
just a couple miles away...
Living on the edge.
...a legit smokehouse...
I'm with you on that
all day long.
...where the brew might be
bringing 'em in...
Genius move.
...but the menu
keeps them coming back.
Brother, I am impressed.
♪♪
So I'm here on the south side
of Minneapolis, Minnesota,
about 5 miles away from the Mall
of America and from the airport.
Now, I'm here
to check out a joint
that started up in a crazy way.
Well, they didn't get start-up
money from the bank,
and they didn't get start-up
money from family.
They didn't get any
crowd funding.
No, what they did is they said
they'll give you beer for life.
That's my kind of joint.
This is Northbound Smokehouse
and brewpub.
♪♪
Cuban Reuben up!
You can't get this
in every neighborhood.
Smokehouse platter.
The best brews and best
smokehouse food you can find.
FIERI: But Amy Johnson
and Jamie Robinson
almost didn't get to open
this place back in 2012.
The bank didn't give them
the loan they wanted,
so they reached out
to the community.
If you invested $1,000,
you'd have free beer for life.
Genius move.
How many people did it?
Uh, 75 people.
Beer is what we really came for,
and now we stay for the food.
Barbecue pork tacos!
FIERI:
And all the cooking cred
goes to Chef Jason Foster,
who's working against
his own challenges.
I'm blind completely in one eye
and legally blind in the other.
What?
Smell and taste --
that's all your need,
and ears.
Brother,
I am impressed.
Chef Jason's
a really innovative cook.
True to the Minnesota flavor,
he smokes everything.
Smoked jerk wings
in the window!
Smoked wings are so good.
What are we
gonna make first?
We're gonna make the brine
for the smoked wings.
So we start with hot water,
add the salt, brown sugar.
I'm gonna whisk
that together.
Now I'm gonna pour this
into the larger bus tub.
Worcestershire.
Okay.
Black peppercorns.
What kind of beer is this?
This is our smokehouse porter.
We make it in-house.
We actually smoke the grains
for it.
You smoke the grains?
Correct.
Okay.
Wings?
Wings right there.
How long will you let
these brine, Chef?
24 hours.
And then they go
to the smoker?
Correct.
How long do those
wings smoke?
Hour and a half.
Now it's time
for the rub.
Yes, sir. Thyme.
Black pepper.
Paprika.
Ooh.
That's some
orange paprika.
[ Chuckles ]
A little clove?
That's a lot of clove.
Cinnamon.
Chili powder.
Some kind of an allspice?
Yep.
Garlic powder.
Okay.
Brown sugar.
White sugar.
Then next will be salt?
Put the lid on it
and shake it up.
This is the dry rub
we put on the wings
when they come out
of the fryer.
Do you serve
any dipping sauce?
Blue cheese dressing.
Start with the blue cheese
crumbles.
Buttermilk.
Mayonnaise.
Sour cream. Minced onion.
Minced garlic.
Are you bringing it
close enough
that you were actually
smelling it?
I can see color.
Okay.
I'm just checking.
I don't -- I don't know
your ninja ways, Chef.
Smokehouse porter.
White distilled vinegar.
Salt and pepper.
Yeah.
Give it a good stir.
All right, let this set up.
Now we're gonna fry
our smoked wings.
Hit it with a little
jerk seasoning.
Into the basket.
♪♪
Mmm.
Nicely done, man.
The rub's not super salty.
You can really taste the smoke
coming through.
Not over-smoked,
and the fry at the end
puts that little crisp
on the wing.
And the blue cheese, by the
way -- real flavor in it.
A little acid.
Good texture. Great spice.
I do get even that
small amount of beer.
Nicely done, Chef.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
Smoked jerk-rub wings
with blue cheese.
Crispy on the outside and juicy
and smokey on the inside.
Tastes very tender.
Goes well with beer.
Cheers.
MAN: They have so many
different varieties
that they serve and make.
WOMAN: Right now,
I'm drinking the porter.
I have a feeling that
it's somewhere also
in my porketta sandwich,
which is amazing.
MAN: 18-hour porketta
in the window.
That quintessential
Minnesota dish.
All right, Chef.
We're making the dried spice rub
for our 18-hour porketta.
Let's get after it.
All right.
Fennel seed.
Black pepper, salt.
Garlic powder. Oregano.
Basil.
Give it a good stir.
So we're not
going traditional
with the porketta with the belly
and the whole thing?
We are doing a Boston butt,
specifically.
This is
a pulled-pork porketta.
Yes.
Living on the edge.
Let's see this.
I have to butterfly
our Boston butt.
We leave the bone in.
It adds an extra layer
of flavor.
I'm with you on that
all day long.
Take our dry rub.
Next, our garlic.
You're laying it on there.
Flavor.
Get it, brother.
Fennel.
We're gonna just drop in
more of the fennel,
and we'll just stack that
in there.
I want to add a little more
fennel to the top.
There you go.
That's right.
Next, our smokehouse
porter again.
And then we
cover it in foil.
And then that goes into
the smoker for...
18 hours.
Look at that.
We are ready to make a sandwich
with it.
No flavor in that,
I can just tell you from here.
Okay.
A little sauteed onion.
[ Sizzling ]
What kind of
cheese was that?
Swiss.
Steam that up,
melt the cheese.
Building a little
crust on that.
That's ready to go.
Ah, that's beautiful.
I'm just trying
to pace myself
and not shove
the entire sandwich
in my mouth at one time.
[ Chuckles ]
It's succulent,
tender pork,
with a lot of that big flavor
from the garlic and the fennel.
The sauteed onions
is a very nice touch.
Your Swiss cheese
is spot-on.
♪♪
Thank you.
Nicely done, Chef.
WOMAN:
18-hour porketta.
Amazing. Caramelized onions
on top of a heap of meat.
Was that a heap of meat?
Mm-hmm.
Come on down
for a heap of meat.
Smoked wings and a Reuben,
table 97.
MAN: Great food,
have great beer.
It's perfect for
this neighborhood.
You know, you have a little bit
of a debilitating piece
with the eyesight,
but it does not stop you
or slow you down one bit.
I think you're
an inspiration, man.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Humming theme from "Jaws" ]
[ Laughter ]