Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
This trip...
Here we go.
We got a little island fever.
It's fantastic.
Mixed with big Italian flavor.
That's totally
the way I like it.
In Plymouth, Massachusetts.
You are the pilgrim
of Flavortown.
A chef giving plantains
new purpose...
Now you're gonna do
your magic.
While winging it
with bananas.
Banana like banana,
banana, banana?
In Colorado Springs...
Come on down,
we're having a ball.
...a neighborhood
Italian joint...
I wouldn't change a thing
about this.
...getting back to the basics.
That's a real-deal,
old-school Italian dish.
Plus, a Caribbean fusion spot.
Hear it every day.
Putting the rasta into pasta.
As weird as the whole thing
sounds, it's really good.
That's all right here,
right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives!"
♪♪
So I'm here
in Plymouth, Massachusetts.
That's right, that Plymouth.
Now, right down the way here
on Water Street,
oh, you'll find the Mayflower,
you'll find Plymouth Rock.
And right here
in front of Plymouth Harbor,
you got a funky little joint
that's discovered by tourists
and loved by locals.
This is the Blue-Eyed Crab.
Picking up jerk chicken,
table four, please.
Really good stuff.
WOMAN: The guava pork chops.
I like it 'cause it's different,
it's creative, fresh.
Is this the typical
type of food
you'd find
in the Cape Cod area?
You're not gonna get this
anywhere else.
And it's all because of Jim.
FIERI:
That would be Chef Jim Casey,
a food veteran from New York,
who looked to America's hometown
to open this place in '07.
Well, I wanted to see the ocean
every day
and get
some fresh air.
And then you're scratch-making
all your food.
Yep.
FIERI: Well, what makes this
place unique in these parts...
Lobster-crab Creole.
I went a little more
with the Caribbean twist.
Sometimes you see something on
the menu you wouldn't expect
and you're not sure about,
and then you eat it,
and it completely blows you
away.
Banana-garlic wings.
WOMAN: You wouldn't guess
that garlic and banana
would pair well together,
but it's great.
Banana like banana,
banana, banana?
There's bananas in there,
yeah.
That's bananas.
Okay, well, let's get into it.
We're gonna put some star anise
in there, cinnamon sticks,
some jalapeños,
fresh garlic.
And where'd the recipe
come from, Chef?
Pretty much flavors
that I like.
Okay.
Oh, so mine would have some
tequila, some beef jerky.
We could definitely do
that.
Some fresh ginger,
sugar to get a little
caramelization on that.
Orange juice
and some soy sauce.
All right, so I'm just
gonna take a few of these,
marinate it overnight.
They go to the grill,
they go in a fryer --
how do they get done?
We roast them.
We roast them
for about 30 minutes,
and then we get a nice char
on them on top of the grill.
All right.
Let's hit it, Captain.
What are we making?
This is the sauce for the
banana-garlic wings.
Okay.
We start off with a little
butter -- unsalted.
Okay.
Pop some garlic
in there.
When this is nice
and toasted,
we're gonna put
all the other ingredients in.
Okay.
That's some fish sauce,
sweet chili sauce,
orange juice,
maple syrup.
Kitchen sink.
Some fresh OJ.
Banana liqueur.
Eye of newt.
And some orange zest.
Wing of bat.
And fresh bananas.
Kind of weird.
So once it starts
to simmer,
we're gonna drop it
and puree it?
Exactly.
Smells great.
Gonna be good.
All right.
Let's get a little bit
in the pan.
So we're just gonna glaze this
right up.
Throw five plantains
in there.
Then we throw the wings
So we're gonna garnish the plate
with a bit of greens.
Grab the wings.
Serve this
with a tropical cream.
So what I do is take
pineapple juice,
cook it down
with just a touch of sugar.
And then we fold it
with a little bit of sour cream.
It's our own ranch dressing.
And we garnish it
with a little scallions.
That's Flavortown passport
right there.
Kind of like a calypso band
meets Metallica
with Eric Lindell
doing the lead singing.
That's exactly
what I was thinking.
I mean, it's all over
the board,
picking up that fish sauce,
picking up that OJ.
I get a little bit
of that tang,
I'm getting the star anise
coming through,
with just a bite
of that cinnamon.
And then you get yourself
a little plantain with it
and a little bit
of the tropical...
Cream.
It's SPF 40, too,
so we're all set.
Zinc oxide.
They're juicy,
they're very tasty.
A little sweet,
a little heat, a little spice.
The dipping sauce, too,
is just out of this world.
Picking up seafood stew!
I feel like
I'm in the Caribbean.
WOMAN: You're almost like
in old San Juan or something.
It has that vibe.
FIERI:
All the bright colors.
And it has that island feel.
And so does the food.
Jerk chicken in here
is really great.
FIERI: Which you might expect
in a Caribbean joint.
What you don't expect
is what they're serving it on.
Picking up
the Jibarito Plantain Sandwich.
The who-bitty-hee?
Jibarito.
It means
country bumpkin.
It's a plantain sandwich.
One of the best sandwiches
on the planet, no question.
FIERI: When we come back.
That is
a righteous sandwich.
FIERI: The Blue-Eye Crab
in Plymouth, Massachusetts,
may be in the heart
of tourist central,
but that doesn't stop the locals
from making this
their regular joint.
We come here every week.
You feel like even though you
live here, you're on vacation.
FIERI:
Could be the Caribbean feel
and the food that goes with it.
His jerk chicken
is second to none.
FIERI: Served straight up
or on a sandwich.
Jibarito
Plantain Sandwich.
Instead of bread, you have a
friend plantain is your crust.
It's wonderful.
FIERI: All right, brother,
what are we into now?
We're making the jerk paste
for the jerk chicken.
We throw in
a little chopped garlic,
some scallions,
chopped onions.
Some soy sauce.
Okay.
Fresh habaneros.
Sugar, paprika.
Okay.
Allspice, dried thyme,
cinnamon again,
and then some salt
and pepper.
Got it.
Oh!
That's a nice heat.
All right.
So instead of putting
any mustard in the jerk paste,
I put the mustard
right on the chickens.
Then rub them
with the paste.
And then how long we let them
sit there and marinate?
Overnight, 24 hours.
How long is it gonna go on
the rotisserie for?
Hour and a half.
All right, so now we have
a green plantain.
Yep.
I've had some fights
with these.
Yeah.
And the greener
they are,
the more difficult they are
to peel.
Correct.
Cut the ends off,
go in a little bit...
Then I take it,
cut it right in half.
Now, we'll drop that in
the fryer just till it cooks.
Now you're gonna do
your magic.
Yep.
Got to press it enough
to flatten it,
but not too much
that you break it.
Not bad.
Take a spatula.
Got to be nice to it.
Take the next one.
Here we go!
You'll actually feel it
kind of give a little bit.
There we go.
Back to the fryer.
About two minutes.
Just so it crisps up
enough,
but still stays nice
and pliable.
And that's our bread.
That's it.
Take this chicken,
pull it right off.
Break it down.
And now, I just take a little
bit more of the jerk paste.
Okay.
And I want to add a little bit
more flavor to it.
[ Whistles ]
Some scallions.
Warm it up
in the skillet.
Put a little blended oil
in there
and we'll just throw the chicken
right in.
Take a little guacamole,
spread that out.
Some key lime aioli.
Pickled onions,
some queso fresco.
Nice mild cheese.
Then we take some greens.
Okay.
Then we add
the chicken.
That is sexy.
That is all set.
Dude...
It's fantastic.
Thank you.
All right.
It's crisp,
it stays together,
it tastes just like if you'd
taken a piece of sourdough bread
and put it in
a Panini machine.
The pickled onions
are the key.
Just enough aioli,
just enough of the guac.
You are the pilgrim
of Flavortown.
[ Laughs ]
Well done.
Oh!
The chicken has
a smoked flavor to it.
I love the idea of the plantain
instead of bread.
WOMAN: Just a fabulous place
to come for dinner --
or lunch, or drinks.
WOMAN: It's like my living room.
I feel like
it is my second home.
I feel like I've been sitting in
your kitchen at your house.
Everybody's having
a good time.
What a fun place, man.
FIERI:
Coming up in Colorado Springs...
Another one of
those swimsuit dishes.
...legit Italian recipes...
On-point, man.
Thank you.
...served with a side
of flair.
You got half New Jersey,
the rest Colorado,
and then forget about it.
FIERI:
So I'm here on Colorado Avenue
in old Colorado City,
which is a neighborhood
of Colorado Springs
in the state of Colorado.
Wow, that's a lot of Colorados.
Anyhow, you know how everybody
on their phone
has an app for finding
this place or that place?
I don't need that.
You see, because I have GPS.
That's right,
that's the Guido Pasta Search,
and this is what I found.
This is Paravicini's.
This is like Sunday dinners
at home.
That's hot.
Every dish is so tasty.
It started out with Franco
cooking his mother's recipes.
FIERI: Which are
the southern Italian dishes
that chef and owner
Franco Pisani
has been stirring up
since he opened in 2003.
Forget about it.
We eat, we drink,
we have a good time.
This guy's got it going!
You got half New Jersey,
the rest Colorado,
and then forget about it.
We love Franco.
He's not a wallflower.
Every guest we have
in our house, they come here.
All our friends come here.
It's very comforting.
Great comfort food.
Arancini!
Arancini is amazing.
Crunchy rice balls
with fresh peas inside.
MAN: Yeah, I love it.
The pesto and the Romano cheese
just pops.
All right,
so we're gonna make the pesto.
Go for it.
Fresh basil.
Okay.
Then we're gonna add
a little bit of oil.
Pine nuts.
Do you make
the pesto every day?
Every day.
Parmigiano-Reggiano cheese.
Okay.
[ Whirring ]
Forgot the garlic.
Did you put the garlic
in there?
Forgot the garlic.
It's looking good.
Andy time
you forget something,
I take another piece
of your bling.
All right.
Starting with
the gold watch.
So pesto's done.
That's the foundation
of the sauce.
Okay.
I want to make
the cream sauce, Béchamel.
Okay.
That you make in-house?
Yes.
Pesto.
I like that pesto,
it's got a little grit to it.
Butter,
Parmigiano-Reggiano cheese.
There we go.
We're done.
Let me try this.
Now, do you make it
in the pan each time,
or do you make it
in large batches?
No, we make it in the pan
each time.
You just come
and get that.
Next up, the Arancini?
Yep.
Olive oil, red onions.
I like the red onions.
They're a little bit sweeter,
you know what I mean?
And then we're gonna add
the Arborio rice.
Toast the rice off.
A little bit, yeah.
And this is chicken stock.
I can see
from all the oil floating
that this is
your own chicken stock.
Absolutely.
Fresh butter.
Some Parmigiano-Reggiano
cheese.
You're not light
with it.
Now a little salt
and pepper.
All right, so this is gonna go
for about 45 minutes?
Yeah, about 45 minutes.
Okay.
Mmm!
That homemade
chicken stock,
all the difference
in the world, man.
Then we're gonna lay it out
on the sheet pan.
And then
let this cool down.
Okay, so this is our risotto
that's congealed up.
Yep, and we're gonna make
a nice little ball out of it.
Come on down,
we're having a ball.
You're gonna put your finger
in there,
put a couple peas,
little bit of cheese.
Okay.
Flour.
Egg and then bread crumbs.
There we go.
How many come
with an order?
Three.
Three of them.
Tree do?
What kind of tree
is that?
Arancini tree.
Don't you have one?
All right,
into the fryer.
And then we're gonna take
the sauce we made
and plate it all up.
More cheese,
'cause you don't get enough.
That's it right there.
That's a nice crust
on that.
Look at that.
Sweet peas in the middle.
Mm-hmm.
Believe it or not,
I still get that chicken stock
from the beginning
of the risotto.
Mm-hmm.
The fact that you make
that pesto cream sauce
fresh every day,
that basil is so sweet
and so delicious.
Mmm!
Great job.
Perfect, thank you.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
What I really like is the pesto.
It just kind of compliments
the texture of the rice.
MAN: It's a great dish
to get started,
get your tongue waking up
for what's to come.
FIERI: This is the way
your nona was making it,
your mom
was making it?
Absolutely.
Absolutely -- maybe better!
MAN:
This does remind me of Italy.
The older building,
more of a neighborhood here.
FIERI: Which makes sense
with a name like Paravicini's,
since it basically translates
to "for the neighborhood".
FIERI:
This is a pretty cool hangout.
It feels like a house.
Nice open kitchen.
PISANI: People come in
and it's like going to my house.
We make everything.
Everything.
Right at the time.
So if you tell me,
look,
I don't like
sun-dried tomatoes,
you don't have to
have them.
Wedding soup!
Franco cares a lot
about his food.
He wants to make sure
everybody's happy.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
I like the veal.
Veal Giuseppe!
The Veal Giuseppe
is an explosion of flavor.
MAN: With the peppers
and the sausage,
it's tickling your nose
before you even start to eat.
Next up is the...
Veal Giuseppe.
So you just kind of set it up
that, you know what,
we'll name something after
Guy's great-great-grandfather.
My grandfather
was Giuseppe.
Your grandfather
was Giuseppe?
My grandfather
was Giuseppe.
When Hunter was born,
I tried to name Hunter Giuseppe.
And when Ryder was born,
I tried to name him Giuseppe.
She didn't go for it.
So the fact that now
at least we have a veal dish.
Veal dish.
...here in Colorado,
that makes me feel
somewhat more complete.
You could put this dish
on one of your menus.
Yes, this is --
I'd be honored.
I want to put this dish
in my face.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, pounding out
the veal.
Dredge it in a little bit
of salt, pepper, flour.
Yeah.
Okay.
Sauteing the veal.
Golden brown.
We're gonna start
building flavor.
Okay.
Okay, a little bit
of red onions.
Kalamata olives, capers,
roasted peppers.
Spicy Italian sausage.
Okay.
Cherry peppers.
Italian cherry peppers, man,
you can't beat 'em.
Forget about it.
A little chicken stock,
a little butter.
We're gonna let that
reduce.
Another one of
those swimsuit dishes.
A little capellini.
Plate up the veal,
put all the sauce
and the goodies on top.
A little parsley
for color.
All right.
And this is how
you get it done.
That's it.
That's totally
the way I like it.
Not too much flour on it,
nice and tender.
It's got
a lot of bold flavor,
but then it's really nice
and delicate.
I wouldn't change a thing
about this.
That's a real deal,
old-school Italian dish.
If you're gonna name that
after your grandfather,
it better be
that great.
On-point, man.
Thank you.
Plating that Giuseppe
right now.
MAN: What I like about this,
it's got that nice spice to it,
but not too hot, though.
I love this place.
It's my favorite.
Well done, brother.
Well done.
Thank you, buddy.
FIERI: Up next...
Ready to rock.
We're staying
in Colorado Springs
for an island Italian mash-up...
What a funky dish.
...filled with the unexpected.
Who came up with
this crazy concoction?
I'm here in Colorado Springs,
Colorado.
Got to love it.
They got it all.
See the Air Force Academy,
Pikes Peak.
They got the Garden of the Gods.
They've got --
This place
is off the hook, man!
They got little "Triple-D" kids,
and a funky joint serving up
Caribbean-Italian food.
This is Rasta Pasta.
Hey, you ever thought
about being on TV?
Chicken Montego Bay.
WOMAN:
You're gonna get something
probably you've never had
before.
The Tortellini Jamaica Mon.
Caribbean and Italian food.
Dreadlock
Ravioli Sausage.
What a crazy idea --
and yet, it works.
FIERI: Which is what initially
hooked husband and wife
Rebecca and Matt Taraborelli and
Rebecca's brother, Greg Harris.
REBECCA:
Rasta Pasta is actually
a long-time 20-plus years
Colorado legend.
FIERI: That someone else owned,
then closed in the ski town
of Breckenridge.
But this crew liked
the original so much
they opened up their own
in 2009.
We like to say
we're a Caribbean pasta joint.
Hear it every day.
Rasta Pasta, let's go!
It's penne with a really rich
spicy red sauce
mixed with some jerk chicken.
It's really delicious.
Okay, so this is
the jerk seasoning.
Basis for a great many
of our dishes.
Well, hit it.
Right here,
we got garlic powder,
onion powder,
black pepper.
Cayenne.
That's a nice little spice.
We got some basil,
thyme, ginger.
Got it.
And here's
the key ingredient.
Nutmeg.
Nice.
This is where we really make
the jerk our own.
We're gonna add
some red pepper flake.
Just a little bit,
though.
Spice it up a little bit.
Just a little bit.
A little sugar.
We got some salt in there.
A tremendous amount
of allspice.
To really make it jerky.
Now we go to
our wet ingredients.
Habaneros.
That's culinary masonry.
That's right.
Hot and good, buddy.
Okay.
Some lime juice
in there.
Apply this
to the chicken.
Yes.
But not traditional
jerk chicken.
Okay.
So I put a little garlic
in a hot pan here,
a little bit of orange juice
used to deglaze.
To that, we'll add our jerk
seasoning we just made there.
So we're not rubbing the
jerk seasoning on the chicken?
No, no.
We do our own thing.
We give it a bit of
an orange juice bath now.
Okay, now.
Boil it in orange juice,
I know,
it's unconventional.
There we go.
Yes.
Just a dab of soy sauce
for color,
a little saltiness.
And who came up with
this crazy concoction?
The story has it
a Cordon Bleu chef
was the original owner
of Rasta Pasta.
Okay.
Created all the recipes
and then sold it
to this other gentleman.
So this is like
the telephone game, dude, okay?
It went to zest it
with some orange
to boil it in orange juice
for six hours.
Exactly.
So how long
is this gonna cook?
40 minutes.
So we're cooking
our Rasta Pasta.
Get after it.
Starting with garlic oil,
a little red wine
to deglaze.
Hey!
We'll add our chicken,
tomatoes, jerk seasoning.
Okay.
Dry spices --
basil, oregano.
A little chicken stock.
Okay.
So now at this point,
we cook our par-cooked noodles
in the pan.
Got it.
We add our marinara.
Oh!
Touch of lime.
A little green onion.
And we are ready to plate,
my friend.
We're ready to rock.
You said you're gonna make
Jamaican jerk Italian food.
Mm-hmm.
That's exactly
what you did.
A really nice dish.
Chicken's super tender.
The allspice, the nutmeg,
not too much heat.
Pasta's perfectly cooked.
I mean, finishing it
in the pan there,
I'll give you
all that.
A little extra lemon juice right
at the end ties it together.
Well done, man.
What a funky dish.
The Rasta Pasta.
Chicken and the red sauce
is a really good combination.
Got a little bit of spice to it,
but not too much.
WOMAN: You can't get this
anywhere else.
Once you come in,
you're kind of hooked.
When I walk in the door,
it just feels like arms open.
FIERI: Very happy place in here.
"One Love"
is our primary product.
MAN: It's about the vibe,
the fun, the spirit.
HARRIS:
The Natural Mystic Veggetti.
Curry like in
the Jamaican style.
With this new veggetti.
It's an amazing substitute
for pasta.
All right, home slice.
This is curry powder.
We got our turmeric.
Okay.
Coriander, cumin.
Got it.
A little salt,
dried mustard, fenugreek.
Fenugreek! Okay.
Mace.
All right.
Ginger, cinnamon,
and Cayenne for that love.
Smells like the spice market
in Bahrain.
Okay.
Next step,
make the veggetti.
I have a buddy named
Gary Maggetti.
Maggetti, veggetti.
Hey, Gary Veggetti!
We're into spiralizing
the veggies.
Now, we use these
on "Guy's Grocery Games",
and these things
are wicked-cool.
So we spiralize out
the yellow squash, the zucchini,
the carrots
so it will make its own pasta.
Nothing but beautiful,
healthy veggies.
Love it.
Okay.
Salt, garlic,
white wine.
Just a dash of soy.
Is that canned pineapple?
Yes.
Jerk chicken.
A little tab of butter
at the start.
Our curry
that we made.
Put in
some pineapple juice.
The veggetti noodles.
[ Whistles ]
The last little dose
of butter,
handful of green onions.
And this is
the Natural Mystic.
[ Chuckles ]
I don't know who thinks about
putting canned pineapple in
with chicken with a jerk spice
and curry,
but as weird
as the whole thing sounds...
The squash and the zucchini
and the carrots
have got good bite
to them.
The pineapple isn't
so identifiable, like,
"Oh, this is
a big pineapple dish."
I tell you something,
it really is a surprising dish.
Mmm!
Your Natural Mystic Veggetti.
It's a combination of things
that shouldn't be put together.
Kind of not something I would
normally order on a menu.
But that's what makes it nice,
it's just unique and different.
HARRIS:
Caribbean Curry Bread.
So excited to have a place
like this in Colorado Springs.
You got to stop here.
Nice job, man.
Nice job.
You guys are crazy.
So that's it
for this Flavortown road trip.
But don't you worry.
there's plenty more joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives".
FIERI: Hey, you ever thought
about being on TV, man?
Yeah!
You have an agent?
An agent?
I'm gonna put a down payment
on your contract.
What do you think?
You're the best.
I don't know
if I'm the best, dude.
You just stole the show!