I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for London's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
That's right.
This trip...
Yes!
We're heading
across the pond...
[ British accent ]
We're gonna get all pretty
with it, aren't we?
[ Normal voice ] ...taking a big
bite out of Britain.
Who's Guy's little piggy?
And, of course,
we're covering the classics...
Beautiful.
...like fish and chips...
That's crazy.
...cranked up
"Triple D"-style.
Dude, I've never
had that before.
Have you not, no?
Shepherd's pie.
Look at this.
This one's off the charts.
Oh, yeah.
That's perfect.
And check out these blokes...
You have license to grill.
-Thank you, mate.
...cooking up true,
blue American 'cue.
That is good barbecue
like you would find
at any barbecue joint
in the States.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives" in London.
♪♪
So I'm here on the east side
of London.
You got everything you'd
expect -- the double-decker bus,
the people driving
on the wrong side of the road,
the steering wheel's
on the wrong side of the car.
And for the food -- Well,
they got all the usual suspects.
You got your bangers and mash.
You got your fish and chips.
And how surprised was I
to get the waft
of killer barbecue smoke coming
through the car.
This is Grillstock Barbecue
Smokehouse.
One full rack of ribs.
It's authentic.
It's the real deal.
This is a taste of America
in the U.K.
-The meat is just so tender.
-One brisket plate.
WOMAN: If I hadn't ridden
the Tube on my way over here,
I would have thought that I
was transported back to the U.S.
FIERI: That's 'cause co-owners
Jon Finch and Ben Merrington
learned from the pros
in the American barbecue circuit
before opening in 2015.
What did you see in the barbecue
scene in the United States
that inspired you
to come do this?
I think it's
the culture of it.
It's a kind of food
that brings people together.
And I don't think
there's a lot of foods do that.
One brisket plate.
One pulled pork plate.
The, um, pulled pork
is just mouthwatering.
The house barbecue sauce
is really great.
It's kind of really fruity.
FINCH: We're about to make
the dry rub for our pork.
So, you're bringing
in full shoulders?
-Yes.
-Okay. Hit the dry rub.
So we're got the paprika,
salt...
How did I end up doing
this part?
I don't know.
You're good, though.
Onion powder, garlic powder,
white sugar...
Little white sugar.
Brown sugar,
some chipotle...
What?
Chipotle, chipotle,
uh, black pepper...
-Okay.
-English mustard powder
and a kick
with some Cayenne pepper.
So now, this dry rub
goes onto the butt?
Liberally on, yeah.
And are we gonna let
this set up a little bit?
-3 or 4 hours.
-Okay.
So now, this is gonna go
into the smoker
for around 18 hours.
225 F, 110 C.
They're American smokers,
so they run Fahrenheit.
Yes!
But we --
Well, that goes...
Thank you.
I get so lost in this Celsius.
I got to have a slide ruler
and some smart person next to me
to get it straight.
All right.
What -- what sauce
is this we're making?
So this is our standard
house sauce.
This goes on
pretty much everything we do.
-Okay.
-So first in, the ketchup,
then
some ballpark mustard.
You guys
don't have ballparks.
That's what we call it,
ballpark.
Honey,
some white wine vinegar,
Worchestershire,
brown sugar,
sautéed onions and garlic,
then house rub.
And how long are we gonna
let this cook down?
Uh, just simmers
for about 15 minutes.
Next,
what are we gonna make?
So now we're gonna
make our house pickles.
They're like a sweet,
sweet pickle.
-Cucumbers and peppers.
-A few onions.
So they've salted
for about 4 hours.
-Right.
-We've got white vinegar,
sugar, plenty of,
some turmeric, ground clove...
-There we are.
...celery seeds,
red peppercorns...
-I like this.
-...and yellow mustard seed.
Basically, we just
bring this to a boil.
Now we're gonna pour the
pickling mix over the cucumbers.
And then,
in the fridge 48 hours.
This is our pork shoulder.
We want nice, big clumps
and hunks of it.
Nice bark on that.
Mm.
Not oversmoked,
super tender.
So we take a little bit
of apple juice...
Some sweetness
doesn't hurt anybody.
And you're gonna throw sauce
on it right now.
We tend to pre-sauce.
Some house slaw down,
the house pickles...
And then fries.
And that's it.
That is good barbecue
like you find at any barbecue
joint in the States.
That's a big meal, man.
Pickles are great, the fries,
the bun, the layout.
Making your own sauces...
That's dynamite.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
MAN:
Pulled pork plate.
It's very juicy and tender.
MAN #2: I think the pickles,
they cut through
the kind of smokiness
of the meat.
-Wings plate.
-What kind of barbecue is it?
Texas, Carolina,
Kansas City?
What is this?
-We don't really go regional.
It's the stuff we like.
-You're the greatest hits album.
-Exactly.
MAN #3: Uh, when you walk
into Grillstock,
I think it does feel
like a really traditional
U.S. barbecue joint.
What else you got
up your sleeve?
Uh, we're gonna
make a Lockjaw Burger.
It's everything
you'd want in one big burger.
It's got pulled pork,
couple of burger patties,
brisket, burnt ends.
-Burnt ends?
-And some burnt ends.
What do you know
about burnt ends?
Don't tell me.
When we come back,
we're gonna make burnt ends.
This, I got to see.
♪♪
Here's the deal. We're hanging
out at a barbecue joint,
Grillstock Smokehouse,
in East London.
I will tell you something,
when these dudes say
that they're doing
real-deal barbecue,
I had to check it out.
The pulled pork
was insane.
But now you are going out
on a limb, my friend,
to tell me
you do burnt ends.
-We do burnt ends, yeah.
-Burnt ends.
-One Lockjaw Burger.
-It's massive.
Two beef patties,
burnt ends,
brisket -- It's amazing.
All right. Show me
how you get down with it.
FINCH: Salt.
You're gonna like
this one -- oregano.
Oh, that's an herb
from Oregon.
Must be, yeah.
Garlic powder, some celery salt
and black pepper.
Okay.
Mix that up.
Hit this on here.
It's a USDA brisket
we're using now.
So this is
imported brisket.
You grow them
bigger there.
And we want the bigger,
fattier, juicier brisket.
So, we're fatter
in the United States?
Your cows are fatter
in the United States.
Way to -- way to --
way to undo that one.
And how long are we going
in the smoker?
So this is gonna go 12 hours.
-225, as well?
-Yep.
Beautiful brisket.
We're gonna slice
some of this,
and we're gonna make some
burnt ends out of this.
I just got a call
from the office,
and they said they need me
to try this, stat.
I don't usually do that,
but...
They're just calling me.
Yeah.
It's gonna be fine.
That's good.
Sprinkle of the house rub,
squirt the sauce.
And then,
back in the smoker,
225, again,
for about another hour.
So we're gonna
make our Lockjaw Burger.
Do it up.
A couple of burger patties,
cheese,
layer on some pickles.
Next up, pulled pork.
Now we're gonna
go the first burger patty
with the melted cheese, some
of the brisket we just cooked.
Now, the second patty...
You sound so dainty when
you say "the second patty."
And I'm gonna kill you
with this thing,
like, a pound of meat.
And then, these
are the brisket burnt ends.
And this is like
our Thousand Island sauce,
then the lid...
There we go, our Lockjaw Burger.
Good luck.
That's a "Triple D" burger.
It's fantastic brisket.
It's burnt ends.
It's double patty.
Let me get
at this burnt end,
'cause that's how
all this ridiculousness
had even started.
Almost like crunchy, candy beef
around the outside of it.
-Mm.
-Pulls apart.
Nice job, brother.
-Thank you.
Good stuff.
MAN:
A Lockjaw Burger for you.
The burger's great.
It's really, really juicy.
The sauce really,
really cuts through.
Man food.
-Man food.
-Yes.
MAN #2: Right amount of
sweetness, right amount
of, you know, meaty flavor.
Can I just see this
for one second?
Can you just do the --
do the royal wave for me
a little bit
with that barbecue hand?
If it wasn't for the rain,
for the red buses,
I'd definitely think
I was in the States right now.
I'm really glad
I found this because
it's a great introduction
for all the people
that live here to understand
what real barbecue's like.
You have
license to grill.
I mean, you're doing it.
-Thank you, mate.
License to grill.
Run with that one, baby.
FIERI: Coming up, we're headed
west across the city...
All day long, brother.
...to a cool, modern joint...
It is off the hook.
...transforming
an old British staple.
That's an adventure
in fish and chips.
So I'm in here in Camden Town,
London,
about 15 minutes
from Buckingham Palace,
to check out a joint
you'd totally expect.
Exactly, fish and chips.
But not just any fish
and chips joint.
No, these dudes
are all about sustainability
and line-caught fish.
Matter of fact,
they say they like to use
the underrated swimming starlets
of the sea.
This is Hook.
Order up.
Sea bass.
They get fresh,
sustainable fish in every day,
so that means that the menu
will change every single day.
WOMAN: For you.
Cannot compare this
to normal fish and chips.
MAN: To do what the guys
are doing here
is kind of
like reinvent it completely.
FIERI: The guys reimagining
this British classic since 2014
are co-owners Barry Wallace
and Simon Whiteside,
both fish
out of water coming from Dublin.
FIERI:
You're from Ireland.
And you come to London,
and you take their fish
and chips,
and then, you're gonna
spin it up a bit.
Do you just stand out here
and fight the majority
of the mornings, or...
It's a little risky, though.
It's a little risky.
You have die-hard
traditionalists that are saying,
"No. It's not
fish and chips.
It's not
fish and chips."
It's like,
"It's fish and chips."
Classic
and minty mushy peas.
I'm having
the classic panko-crusted cod.
A superb, fresh fish inside.
I haven't tasted mushy peas
with -- with a minty flavor
to it before.
Now we're into the minty
mushy peas.
Minty mushy peas. Does everybody
make them with mint,
No.
or is this just you guys
being weird again?
-It's us being weird again.
-Okay.
Gonna go mint first,
salt, double cream.
-Okay.
I do all this
on a really high heat.
Okay.
We're just gonna bash it
in a little bit.
You can see
it already getting hot.
So now we're gonna strain it?
-Yeah.
I just kind of pop it through
there, through a sieve.
Okay.
Then, we're gonna pop
this straight back
in here, like this.
And then, we're gonna throw
in our petit pois.
You call them
petit pois?
Petit pois,
yeah, little peas.
Oh, they're beautiful.
Mm.
I love peas.
-Yeah, yeah.
So fresh.
-This cooks down.
We blitz it.
Mushy peas are done.
What do we do after this?
-Okay.
So this is our lovely cod.
Just gonna cut
one off here.
So we're just gonna pop
this into our plain flour,
little eggwash.
-Okay.
And then,
we're gonna hit it with panko.
That's all she wrote.
-And this is ready to go.
-Okay.
Put it into our fryer.
-How long will that go?
-About three minutes.
-And how about the chips?
-Gonna drop the chips now.
So now, we're just gonna
take our panko cod out,
season it with our house
seaweed salt.
Okay.
Now we're gonna season them
with our seaweed salt.
Into our box...
-Okay.
Go tartar, fish.
And we're just gonna
do our peas.
And typically,
when you have fish and chips,
you're supposed
to have mushy peas?
Traditionally,
it comes with fish and chips.
-That's light.
-Yeah. Absolutely.
It's not oily.
It's not heavy.
The choice of the panko
gives you that great crunch
that you want.
-Mm-hmm.
But it's thin.
Wow.
-Yeah.
And the chips...
Good texture.
I love the seaweed salt.
All right, now,
minty mushy peas.
There's texture, little bit
of mint, little bit of salt.
The balance is awesome.
-Mm.
I got to tell you,
well done.
And mushy peas
all day long, brother.
MAN: The actual texture
of the fish inside,
it sort of just melts
in your mouth.
Mushy peas are really good,
creamy, buttery, sweet.
WOMAN: Chips are excellent.
It's almost like
Mom's roast potatoes,
but with a bit more of a kick.
All right. So, what makes great
fish and chips?
Really, really fresh fish.
So we only use small fisheries.
Whatever gets landed,
we use within 24 hours.
We let the fishermen
decide what's on the menu,
all these
underrated swimming starlets.
Who says "underrated
swimming starlets"?
Underrated
swimming starlets.
We want to diversify the species
in fish and chips.
Guinness and squid ink
on pass.
This is
Guinness ink tempura hake.
Looks almost like a rock,
but it's fish.
Beautiful, beautiful texture.
It's really, really tasty.
This is hake.
That is an ugly fish.
I think
I was attacked by him.
We break this down.
-Yeah.
-What's up next?
Our oyster
and sorrel sauce.
We're gonna shuck our oysters.
-Okay.
A little bit
of lemon juice, wasabi.
Now we're introducing
wasabi into things.
Yeah. Then,
just a little bit of salt.
Then we're gonna
add some vegetable oil
very, very slowly.
-Okay.
Gonna take the stalks
off our sorrel.
Want to have small flecks,
not too big.
That's crazy.
Dude, I've never had
that before.
Have you not, no?
It's got the creaminess.
It's got the viscosity.
And then,
you get that really nice
underlying tone of the oyster.
We're gonna do
our, uh, tempura.
We have Guinness.
-Okay.
It's like the water
of Ireland.
Yeah.
So we're gonna add our squid ink
and salt.
And then, we're gonna hit it
with our tempura flour.
Okay.
Whisk this
to bring it together.
Okay, so here's the hake.
So then, we're gonna
into our flour.
And then, we're gonna hit it
with our ink tempura.
And then, we're gonna fry it
at 170 degrees Celsius.
Okay.
Now we're gonna place
the oyster-and-sorrel sauce
and then the fish
over the chips.
[ Whistles ]
You get Guinness
right off the bat.
The batter's
nice and light.
Where the adventure
really begins
is when you get
into this aioli.
The richness
of the oyster...
I mean, dude.
Really, what I will call this
is a mature fish and chips.
Spot on, dude.
-Yeah.
Really. I mean,
that's an adventure
in fish and chips.
The fish is very soft
and smooth.
The, uh, wasabi gives a bit
of a kick, as well.
I'm not a fan of oysters,
but this actually works,
the sorrel mixed into it.
It's tasty.
So Ahmed
and Jengus own
the oldest-running
fish-and-chips joint in London.
It's called
Rock and Sole Plaice.
What do you think?
-It's great
to see young blood
coming in,
bringing new ideas
to something.
And they're making a mark
for themselves.
Hook means that you come
here once and you're hooked.
When I came here to, uh,
to London,
the idea was to find a variety
of fish and chips.
I think this is really
a fantastic representation.
Off the hook.
It is off the hook.
It's outstanding.
FIERI: Up next, we're cruising
into Central London...
Voilà.
...to a place cooking
real-deal regional recipes...
It's swimsuit season,
and I'm eating shepherd's pie.
...a little differently
than mum made them.
Oh, you had to go to this level,
didn't you?
♪♪
So I'm here in the Smithfield
Market area of London.
And that building right there,
folks have been buying their
meat for the last 900 years.
So you can imagine, this is not
where a lot of tourists go.
You know, this is where
the locals hang out.
So, what would you expect?
You'd expect a locals'
restaurant, serving up what?
Traditional British fare.
But this joint is doing it
with a little twist.
This is Bird of Smithfield.
Ox cheek in the window.
It's about doing simple things
really, really well.
I've got fish and chips
for you.
The food is just so well done.
It's way more
than just classic English food.
It always lifts my spirits.
Just a perfect vibe in the Bird.
FIERI: Where locals have been
flocking since 2013,
when veteran chef Alan Bird
put his name on the joint.
Bird is the word.
I just wanted to do something
with an accent on British food,
just because that was
what I've grown up with.
And that's
what I enjoyed eating.
WOMAN:
Shepherd's pie for you.
There's no other shepherd's pie
like it.
On a scale of 1 to 10?
11.
Just melts in your mouth.
FIERI: So, what
are we making today?
Shepherd's pie.
We've got two salt marsh
lamb shoulders.
Salt marsh...
Is that an area?
Lamb.
Yeah, next to the sea.
Pretty distinct flavor?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
We're gonna add a bit of oil
to help stick the aromats
and spices to it.
And then, we've got
some chopped rosemary,
chopped garlic, as well,
and chopped thyme, and then,
some sea salt.
Just make sure
it gets well-coated.
Place those inside
a vacuum-packed bag.
I love this.
And now, the lamb shoulder's
ready to be vacuum packed.
And all that flavor
is sealed inside the bag.
-Stays inside.
-Yeah.
Look at that.
I'm getting one of those.
So now, we're gonna cook that
in a combi-steam over.
How long these gonna go?
12 hours?
Yeah.
165 degrees.
What we've got are some
ground, or minced, lamb.
What's the difference
between ground and minced?
You guys call it ground.
We call it minced.
-Just minced.
You guys have a way
of making it sound much sexier.
We're gonna drain it off,
place the pan back on the stove.
And we're gonna
add the mirepoix.
-Okay.
-Chopped garlic,
chopped rosemary,
chopped thyme.
Okay.
So we drop it in.
The brown meat
back into the pan.
We're gonna put the tomato paste
in first.
Got to cook
that out a little bit.
Yeah. Then,
in with our chopped tomatoes.
There we go.
Next up...
Next up, we're gonna
add some lamb stock to it,
Worchestershire sauce,
tomato ketchup.
We have some shredded lamb
going in this, as well?
Yes, we do.
So let's go into it.
There you go,
steamed shoulders.
You got
the lovely pink meat.
Mm. Nice.
Little herb to it.
Garlic's not overpowering.
So those are gonna
get shredded.
Then dropped into the pan.
Yeah.
I mean, this is shepherd's pie
gone wild.
The braise is finished now.
Just place it in there.
We got
warm mashed potatoes.
Put the mash on top.
[ British accent ]
Oh, we're gonna get all
pretty with it, aren't we?
-Yeah.
-[ Normal voice ] Look at that.
Oh, you had to go this level,
didn't you?
Voilà.
That's going in the oven...
-Okay.
...20 minutes.
This is jus that we make
with the lamb stock
to pour over the top
to add a little bit of moisture.
Mm.
That's --
The shredded meat
really adds a lot more depth.
Mm.
Pour that on there.
That's just what I needed.
That's perfect.
Without question,
one of the best shepherd's pies
I've ever had.
I'm sure you've tasted a few
in your time.
You can't tell.
I know you can't.
It's swimsuit season,
and I'm eating shepherd's pie.
I'll come back,
just for that dish.
Outstanding, Chef.
Outstanding.
WOMAN: Shepherd's pie.
The unctuousness
of the slow-cooked lamb
is just stunning.
The gravy's amazing, as well.
I think that's the thing
that really makes it.
Give me the greatest hits.
I know bangers and mash.
I know fish and chips.
What are some of the other
essential British food
that I should be aware of?
You got to try
our braised ox cheek.
WOMAN #2: The ox cheek is
something that I could order
every time I come here.
It is so amazing.
I really love it.
Wow.
Who's Guy's little piggy?
Nice bark up on top.
-Yep.
Delicious.
Oh.
Just everything
about it is lovely.
You've got to try
our rhubarb cheesecake.
WOMAN #2: This is way better
than anything
my mother
could ever put together.
Oh, my gosh.
And then, you've got goat curd
in that cheesecake.
Mix that with the sour that
you're pulling off the rhubarb.
It is far more complex and fun
than regular cheesecake.
Very nicely done, Chef.
MAN: Well, we're very lucky,
in Britain,
to have our own heritage and
our own pride in our own food.
And this is the perfect example
of all of those things
coming together.
You're not
on the beaten path.
People want to find a place
like this and say,
"I went
to this little place
where this guy
makes traditional Brit food,
and it's affordable."
So anyone could come
and eat here.
That's the best attitude
in the world.
That's why you're a man
of the people.
Well,
I got to give a big shout-out
to all the "Triple D" fans
in the U.K.
Man, you said you had
the great "Triple D" joints,
and you weren't lying.
Making the jump over the pond
was totally worth it.
But don't you worry.
"Diners, Drive-ins, and
Dives" will be back in the U.K.
I'll see you next time.
[ Telephone rings ]
I'll get it.
[ British accent ] This is
Grillstock. Yeah.
Yeah.
Today, we're closed.
Uh, just a special day
today, a wedding.
All right. Cheerio.
FINCH: Brilliant.