Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip,
we're visiting joints
keeping it real...
Holla.
...by hanging on to family ties.
I am in awe.
In Atlantic City...
There we go.
...a wife
honoring her husband...
Ooh, I like this.
...cranking out
his down-home cooking.
Wrap it up.
I'll get the car.
In Colorado Springs...
[ Whistles ]
...a legit barbecue spot...
Real-deal righteous.
...taking mom's recipes
to the max.
It weighs, like,
six pounds.
Plus...
TOGETHER: Wowie!
...a Baltimore legacy continues.
You give me greatness.
...with dishes
straight out of Flavortown.
Outrageous.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here on the west side
of Colorado Springs,
in an area known
as Old Colorado City.
Now, right up there,
yeah, that's Pike's Peak.
Everybody knows that.
So, what do you do?
You go up and hike that,
you come down here
and reward yourself with, say,
something
like, uh, I don't know,
some great southern cooking.
This is Front Range Barbeque.
Front Range
is like a local landmark.
Pulled chicken plate up.
The food is fabulous.
Lots of flavor.
Smoked wings,
mustard-wine sauce.
Brian, the owner,
is from Alabama.
How'd you get to Colorado?
Got out of school
and headed west
and stopped in Colorado
to see some friends.
Never left.
FIERI:
And Brian Fortinberry put down
some serious roots in 2000
when he opened this place,
featuring his family's
southern specialties.
WOMAN: All the meats
here are really smoky,
which has a lot of flavor.
MAN: Sloppy Pig.
This pulled-pork sandwich
is definitely more than average.
WOMAN: It's pulled pork
with grilled sausage and bacon,
as well as cole slaw,
all on top of this bun.
What are we gonna make?
-Our Sloppy Pig sandwich.
-Our Sloppy huh?
Sloppy Pig.
First, we're making
the dry rub?
This is
my mom's recipe.
Oregano, dry mustard,
onion powder,
a little meat tenderizer,
black pepper,
chili powder, brown sugar,
some of our house-smoked salt.
-Very nice.
-Lemon pepper.
-That's the kicker.
-Granulated garlic.
Turmeric, and cayenne.
Boneless pork butt.
And we're gonna
rub them down.
This is
my mom's dry rub.
So I'm gonna let this rest
in the cooler for 24 hours.
And we're gonna smoke it
for about 14 to 16 hours.
-What kind of wood?
-We're gonna use a hickory wood.
At 225?
Just about 220.
Sweet-and-spicy
barbecue sauce --
a little ketchup,
a little dark corn syrup,
orange juice,
Coca-Cola,
red-wine vinegar,
cider vinegar.
That's
some vegetable oil.
[ Whistling ]
Liquid Smoke.
And we got some
gluten-free soy sauce,
pickle juice.
He hates whistling.
I knew somebody
told you that.
Do you know how
to whistle?
I don't.
Well,
that's your problem.
[ Whistles ]
-Ow!
That's whistling.
A little brown sugar,
a little chili powder.
This is
an interesting one.
A little
dehydrated garlic.
It rehydrates
really well.
Black pepper,
rubbed sage,
crushed red pepper,
Cayenne, dehydrated onion.
Why?
'Cause you can.
I'm learning.
A little
granulated garlic.
And we got
a little celery salt.
I like that.
So we'll cook this
for about an hour,
let it thicken up.
We're gonna be serving this
with the Sloppy Pig.
Love the name.
Good-looking butt.
Now look at the crust on this --
nice bark.
Mmm!
Tasty, brother.
So, we're gonna
shred the pulled pork,
Got to dig through
that layer of delicious fat.
Mix it all.
This is our
sweet-potato bun.
We're gonna throw
some of our
grilled kielbasa sausage
on there.
Pecan-smoked bacon.
Top it
with smoked cheddar cheese.
So I put this
in the oven now.
Out of the oven --
a little bit of our
sweet-and-spicy barbecue sauce,
spicy cole slaw,
our house-fried onion straws,
a couple pickles.
And finally, the top.
You sure there's not one
other thing in the whole kitchen
that you'd like
to put on top of that?
And there we
have our Sloppy Pig.
[ Whistles ]
That's a good-looking
sandwich there.
[ Whistles weakly ]
Close enough.
It weighs, like,
six pounds.
Hi, welcome.
My name's
Gym Membership.
Oh, wow.
It is
real-deal righteous.
Pork's super tender, juicy,
not dried out.
A little char on there,
a little smoke.
That kielbasa, though,
I mean, come on.
I would like to say,
"remove something from this,"
but you would be shortcutting
it if you did.
Wow. Sloppy Pig it is.
Nicely done.
It's just this amazing flavor,
who even knows what.
A woman
and her Sloppy Pig.
I love all the layers --
sweet smoked pork.
Kielbasa sausage
is grilled to perfection.
There's this amazing cole slaw.
It has just the slightest bit
of spiciness.
Look at her go.
It's a girl's dream
who loves bacon.
The food's really, really good,
but the music's excellent.
Some of my favorite bands from
across the country come here
and you just get to let loose.
There's always a great
Colorado beer on tap.
It just --
it feels kind of like home.
FIERI: Nothing says home
like mom's meat loaf.
Meat loaf special
coming down.
I can just gobble it down.
Oh, look,
he's passed out.
No, just had
the meat loaf.
When we come back.
♪♪
So, welcome back.
We're in Colorado Springs
here at Front Range Barbecue.
I just had
the Sloppy Pig.
I don't want to hear any jokes.
So what are we into?
This is gonna
be our smoked poblano
and andouille sausage
meat loaf.
We top it
with a mushroom gravy.
It's really thick,
and it's smoked.
MAN: The mushroom gravy
is really good.
They put a lot of mushrooms
on it.
It's flavorful.
You can't go wrong.
Making the meat loaf.
Yes, the ground meat and
the ground andouille sausage.
Roasted poblanos
chopped up.
Are those
from Pueblo?
These are locally
from Colorado, yes.
Eggs, a little bit
of our barbecue sauce,
a little lemon pepper,
dried oregano,
house-smoked salt,
celery salt,
a little cayenne pepper,
paprika,
some "Washtershestire"
sauce.
What'd you
just put in there?
"Washtershestire"
sauce.
[ Laughter ]
"Washtershestire"
sauce.
That's what we call it
down south.
-Okay.
-Panko breadcrumbs.
Then we're gonna sauté up
our onions, garlic, our celery.
Take all of this
and just mix it
as good as you can
into the form.
There we go.
And then out on a sheet tray
and then into the smoker.
And how long
in the smoker?
Two and a half hours --
220.
Now we're on
to the mushroom gravy.
So we've got our oil.
Let's get some shallots.
We'll let those
get going.
We'll add a little garlic
to that.
Glaze it
with a little red wine.
Some unsalted butter,
white flour --
make a little roux.
Got a cup
of stout beer.
Look at that.
You guys make
your own beef stock?
It's from the smoked
briskets.
We like to use that
in all our soups...
-Whoa! Party.
-...all our sauces.
I'll let that drop down
a little bit.
A little celery salt,
a little white pepper.
We'll add our mushrooms.
And criminis,
of all mushrooms, huh?
I think they got
a little more flavor to them.
-How long is this gonna go?
-20 minutes.
We're gonna add a little bit
of heavy cream to it.
There you go.
Let's make
some meat loaf.
Big old piece.
Pull it off, served over
our house-made mashed potatoes,
topped with a little bit
of our mushroom gravy.
And a little green-onion
garnish on it.
It's nice, not dried out,
a little crusty on the outside.
Get a little bit of that poblano
coming through right there.
Potatoes
are nice and creamy,
but that mushroom gravy
is spot-on.
This is a nice surprise
compared to what
you'd normally expect
at a barbecue restaurant.
Well-done, brother.
Well-done.
That'll put you
right to bed.
It's good. It's tender.
It's juicy.
It's like coming home.
You're from an old run-down
barbecue joint in Alabama?
I eat here so much sometimes
I feel like I own
part of the place.
What a treat for people
living here in the great state
of Colorado to have
a transport right to the south.
You're doing it right --
all these family recipes.
You're just whistling
your way through this.
Thank you.
[ Whistling ]
Up next in Atlantic City...
Ooh.
...a family keeping
a dream alive...
The good stuff!
...cooking up soul
straight from the heart.
All right.
I'm done.
I'll have a nap.
♪♪
So I'm here in downtown
Pleasantville --
no, really,
Pleasantville, New Jersey,
about five miles
away from Atlantic City.
So I'm here to check out a joint
where a locally renowned chef
wanted to open his own joint
serving up
southern-style comfort food.
This is
Sam's Rialto Bar and Grill.
BRENDA: Turkey chop, table 8.
Pick it up.
Sam's is really a staple
for the community.
-I have a meat loaf platter.
-Yes.
FIERI: If someone
were to say to you,
"I want some
true southern-style
comfort food,"
you would say...
-Sam's Rialto.
-Sam's Bar and Grill.
-Hands-down?
-Yep.
You walk in and you see
Sam's face, you just feel like
he's welcoming you to a piece
of his home.
FIERI: Which is exactly the vibe
Chef Sam Hunter
was all about from the time
he opened this joint in 1983
till he passed in 2008.
You felt like he
lit the whole room up.
He looks like he
lights it up right now.
With the soul-food torch,
his wife, Brenda,
and son, Jake, now carry.
BRENDA: Dark meat and waffle,
pick it up.
When I desire chicken
and waffles,
I come to Sam's Rialto.
Breakfast, lunch, dinner.
Chicken and waffles
are always good.
What are we starting off with?
The chicken and waffles?
First we have to marinate
our chicken.
I add my kosher salt.
Sam always said,
"let it hit it."
Let it hit it.
And then we massage
it in from there.
And was Sam the head chef
here at the time?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Buttermilk.
Good stuff.
And how long
are we gonna let this marinate?
-12 hours.
-Okay.
-Now we're making the dredge?
-We use our all-purpose flour,
pepper, granulated garlic,
dry mustard,
paprika,
onion powder.
And then we're gonna pick out
a nice piece of chicken for you.
There we go.
A little squeeze to get some
of that extra flour in there?
Correct.
And now we just take it
and into the fryer.
And that's all she wrote.
Now, how long is that gonna go?
15 to 20 minutes.
And in the meantime,
we'll make the waffle.
First,
you beat your eggs.
We have our milk,
our vegetable oil.
Now our vanilla,
all-purpose flour,
granulated sugar.
You can add the salt
for me.
Please pass the malt.
-Ooh, I like this.
Makes the outside crispy,
the inside fluffy.
-A little bicarbonate?
-Exactly.
That's the batter.
What kind of waffle maker
are we cooking this on?
Coal-fired? Nuclear?
Electric?
-The one over here.
-Sun?
Oh, the old one.
We make sure you have enough
to spread it all around.
-How long will this take?
-Two and a half minutes.
Then we got our chicken.
Then we dress it
with cinnamon sugar.
Then we have
our maple syrup.
And then we put a spoonful
of butter.
Okay.
I like that little
cinnamon-sugar kiss
you just put on that.
Nice, light batter,
tender chicken.
I think the key to it,
besides great chicken,
is a really nice
homemade waffle
and the fact that you're
making it from scratch.
And that's the way
Sam wanted everything done?
-Sam's way or the highway.
-Nicely done.
The waffles are soft
and golden brown.
The fried chicken
is mouth-watering.
Sam's is a great community
gathering place
for people to come.
I'll sit at the bar
and have a martini.
One of the best martinis
I've ever had.
Rib platter, table 3.
Pick it up.
I eat in here three,
four times a month.
And at least once,
I got to have the ribs.
-Now we're into ribs.
-We use a dry rub.
This is a little
mesquite-smoked salt,
pinch of nutmeg,
some white sugar.
granulated garlic,
cinnamon,
kosher salt, of course,
crushed thyme leaves,
paprika, cumin,
onion powder,
and black pepper.
-Another Sam recipe?
-No.
-No?
-A little add-on.
Who's Little Add-On?
Does he work here?
I add
mesquite-smoked salt.
Because if you
don't have a smoker,
you're gonna need a little bit
of that love, okay.
Rub this in for this.
Now we add brown sugar
to the top.
We don't want too much.
We don't want too little.
I take hard apple cider.
-Ooh!
Put that in the bottom
of the pan.
This makes
a steaming process instead
of using
the typical water.
-"Wooder"?
-That's south Jersey -- water.
-"Wooder."
-Now we can cover this.
Goes to the oven
at 350 for an hour.
Then we'll drop down
and go low and slow?
Correct.
250 for another hour.
Okay,
did you just get taller?
[ Chuckles ]
There's
a big ramp here.
You've got your kale
and you've got your collards.
Okay, so what we do is we use
our homemade chicken broth.
-Okay.
-Then we add our turkey wing.
It's a smoked turkey wing.
-Got it.
Bring that to a boil, and we
just let it cook for an hour.
Put your favorite
seasoned salt in.
It doesn't matter what.
And onion powder,
a pinch of nutmeg.
That's
an interesting one.
-Rachael Ray. Yes.
-Rachael Ray?
A little shout-out
to you, Rach.
Now we're just packing
them in there.
It'll fit all
in this pot.
And once they cook
for that hour?
-We pull the turkey wing out.
-Right, right.
Chop it up
and put it back in the greens.
All right, and then...
Ribs are ready.
How many ribs they get?
We serve four
to an order.
And we take our sauce.
Okay.
We have some homemade
macaroni and cheese, as well.
-Collard greens are next?
-Collard greens are next.
Look at that.
Have a little vinegar
here for me,
a little hot sauce.
I love greens.
Mmm.
Tender like butter.
It's not oversalted.
Love a little bit
of that turkey wing.
Mmm.
I could eat that whole pot.
I've had a few ribs
in my day.
Mmm.
Got a nice bark on it.
I got a little bit
of that cider,
and I get a touch
of smoke.
Laying on
that brown sugar.
Your whole dry rub mix
that you did on it,
I definitely get some sweet
off the top.
All right, I'm done.
I'll have a nap.
Absolutely succulent
and delicious.
Every piece is super tender.
It falls off the bone.
The way this place feels
when I walk through the door,
Sam is very proud.
He's watching this
right now,
just laughing,
having a good time.
Can I have my greens
to go?
Sure, you can have
the whole pot.
That's what I meant.
-Yes.
-Wrap it up. I'll get the car.
Coming up in Baltimore,
a funky spot going big-time
with breakfast...
That's an adult
French toast.
...and killing it
with their crabcakes.
The way you compose
this sandwich is so next-level.
♪♪
So, here I am
in the Roland Park neighborhood
of Baltimore, Maryland,
on Cold Spring Lane.
Well, more fondly known
as Eddie Dopkin Way.
That's because back in the '90s,
Eddie had,
like, five rocking restaurants
in this area.
And the one
he was most widely known for is
a funky big breakfast joint
known as Miss Shirley's Café.
And your shrimp and grits.
This place is unlike any other.
MAN: Miss Shirley's Affair
with Oscar.
It's always a treat.
WOMAN: People will stand in line
for literally an hour,
hour and a half, two hours.
It's something
that is worth the wait.
FIERI: It's something Eddie
would have been proud to see.
My father,
he's really smiling down.
That's 'cause since he
passed in 2013, his son, David,
and daughter-in-law, Brandi,
have carried on what he started.
MAN: They put
an enormous amount
of pride and love
into their food,
and it becomes infectious.
Your coconut-cream
stuffed French toast.
This is definitely a dish
I spoil myself with.
It's two large pieces
of challah.
Stuffed with this amazing cream.
FIERI: Which is the creation
of Chef Brigitte Bledsoe,
who's been
heading up this kitchen
since they opened in 2005.
Chicken waffle.
FIERI: Eddie knew she was big
on talent.
Hey, but when I got here,
she was a little short on voice.
So, what are we gonna make?
-Coconut cream filling.
That's easy for you
to say.
Not really, though.
BLEDSOE: We're gonna start off
with some cream cheese.
We're gonna
add mascarpone cheese.
Mascarpone, okay.
Shredded coconut,
coconut extract.
vanilla extract, honey.
Darling.
Where's this going to go?
We're gonna stuff it
in our challah bread.
Holla!
Then we close it up.
All right,
let's cook it.
we have some whole eggs.
We have heavy cream,
whole milk.
Okay.
Brown sugar.
Rolling Stones.
Ground nutmeg, ground cinnamon,
coconut extract.
If there wasn't enough
coconut in this.
And a little bit
of vanilla.
And now
we're gonna mix this up.
We're gonna go ahead
and dip it in our mix.
It's like a pool raft.
And then put a little bit
of butter.
Okay.
And that probably takes as long
as a prime rib does to cook.
It's gonna
take about 10 to 12 minutes.
-Finish it in the oven?
-Yes.
-Okay.
-And I cut this.
This is
a raspberry purée.
Diced strawberries, and we put
our coconut on here --
a little more
shredded coconut.
Syrup, cinnamon,
powdered sugar, mint,
and brûléed bananas.
Okay.
So, how do I eat it?
Oh.
With a fork
and a knife.
It's delicious.
It's not overly sweet.
I love the texture
of the coconut.
Great texture
on the outside of it,
because you cooked it
a long time with the challah.
The crème brûlée banana
along with the strawberries.
But the thing
that makes it all come together
is the acidity
in the raspberry purée.
That's really great.
-Awesome.
-That's an adult French toast.
-Oh, I like that.
And the coconut-cream
stuffed French toast.
WOMAN #1: Oh, my God.
WOMAN #2: Each bite, you get
the texture of the coconut,
the sweetness with the crunch.
I have no problem
giving it a "wowie."
Did she just drop
a "wowie"?
Wowie!
It's amazing.
Apparently, that's something
you might have heard
when Eddie was around.
One of his favorite expressions
was "Wowie!"
So, this guy was the life
of the party.
-This is a wowie.
-Yeah.
WOMAN: Eddie was a big part
of Baltimore,
and his legacy
still lives on here.
Your crabcake po' boy.
The jumbo lump crab meat with
this Tabasco-bacon-onion jam.
A lot of people in Baltimore
take pride in their crabcakes,
but they're gonna
have to measure themselves
by Miss Shirley's.
What are we
making next?
-A bacon-onion-Tabasco jam.
-Okay.
Olive oil, sweet onions,
chopped garlic.
-Bacon?
-Bacon.
There we go.
Next up?
-Coffee.
-I like where this is going.
Apple-cider vinegar,
maple syrup.
-A little hot sauce.
-Brown sugar,
and a little black pepper.
-Okay.
All of this
is gonna cook down...
For two and a half hours.
So now we're gonna
finally make the crabcake?
Yes.
A little mayo, eggs,
Worcestershire,
Old Bay, yellow mustard,
kosher salt.
Mix this together.
Okay,
what's going on now?
All right,
we have 2 pounds of crab meat.
-Whoa!
-Roasted red peppers,
parsley, crabcake mix.
-Okay.
-This is cracker meal.
So, this is just enough effort
to combine it.
Yes, that's what I call
a crabcake.
I am in awe.
Now, show me what the size
of a crabcake is around here?
2 ounce. Three of them will go
in the sandwich.
Okay.
Now we have
our bacon jam.
Plenty of that on there.
-Okay.
-Old Bay remoulade.
I'll get this for you.
Old Bay remoulade.
Old Bay.
Yeah, bibb lettuce,
red and yellow tomatoes.
-Okay.
And then we have
our mini crabcakes.
Okay.
Gonna garnish with parsley
and Old Bay.
This is outrageous.
The way you compose
this sandwich is so next-level
from the super-unctuous
bacon jam.
In the crabcake, there's only
a little bit of egg and mayo,
and that kiss
of this little cracker crumb.
Cracker meal.
My mom and dad
are both huge crabcake fans.
My old man
would flip out for this.
You give me greatness.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
It's some of the best crabcakes
I've ever had.
I would order it every chance
I got.
I need those strawberry waffles.
When you leave, you always
have a huge smile on your face.
So give it up
for Eddie and a little.
TOGETHER: Wowie!
[ Laughter ]
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry!
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Oh, speechless.
I like that.
-No, that's you.
[ Laughter ]
And the crowd goes wild!
Good night!