Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
...we're hitting dishes
that really stack up...
That's ridiculous.
...on the bun
and between the bread.
Flavortown overload.
In Colorado Springs...
There you go.
...a funky
family-owned burger stop...
Really impressed.
...getting outrageous
with the toppings.
Keep an eye
on this one.
In Atlantic City...
That's just
what I need.
...a joint rising
from the flood waters...
Bang.
...and sailing way
beyond basic bar food.
You're getting
very cosmopolitan on us.
Plus, in Washington D.C...
Keeping it real.
...big-time
culinary creations.
Easily four pounds.
...packed into
serious sandwiches.
Dude, this is, like,
flavor explosion over here
in hoagie heaven.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here
in Washington D.C.,
about 10-minute walk
to the White House
in an area known
as Dupont Circle
to check out a joint
everybody's talking about,
where a family from Philly
is offering up
a real hoagie hotspot.
This is Bub and Pop's.
Half Italian
with French Onion.
The food here is fantastic.
It really is a taste
of Philly in Washington D.C.
FIERI: Brought here by chef
and Philly native Jon Taub,
who opened this joint in 2013
with his mom and step-dad
but named it
after Grandma and Grandpa.
Everybody called them
Bub and Pop.
Everybody.
What kind of restaurant
is this?
ARLENE: We're chef-driven,
and we cook from scratch.
His training
is in classic French cuisine.
My boy tow truck here?
Yep.
This guy?
MAN: He's just brilliant
with the ideas
that he comes up with.
The sandwich plays center stage.
Large Jewish hoagie
for here.
The Jewish hoagie
is a loaded sandwich.
It's packed with turkey
and corned beef and brisket,
and it's just got
this delicious coleslaw
piled on top.
What are we making first?
The brine for our corned beef.
Okay.
Water. Onion.
Carrots. Garlic.
Kosher salt.
Celery.
Fresh thyme.
Okay.
Honey.
Thank you, sir.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you for this.
Appropriate spatula.
[ Laughter ]
Allspice.
Coriander seed.
Okay.
Pink salt.
Black peppercorns.
Dried bay leaves.
And mustard seed.
I literally just bring it
to a boil and kill the heat.
I let it cool down overnight.
So, all those flavors,
they're gonna marry.
Yep.
Brisket's ready to go.
Mm-hmm.
Put holes
all over the brisket
just so the brine
can seep into it.
How long are we gonna let
it sit there in the brine?
14 days.
14 days?
Then when it comes out,
how we cooking it?
We put it in
a roasting pan with mirepoix,
a little bit of water,
plastic wrap, aluminum,
and then
we just braise it.
And once it's cooled down,
we slice it real thin.
Okay, Thousand Island
is on the Jewish hoagie?
Yes, sir.
This is our homemade mayonnaise.
It's basically like
a roast garlic aioli.
Okay.
You make your own ketchup.
Yes, sir.
And these are our
kosher dill pickles.
We make these, too.
Is there anything
you don't make?
We don't make the water.
Keeping it real.
Okay,
let's build this sandwich.
Okay.
So I'm gonna put
a nice little layer of Dijon.
A little bit
of the Thousand Island.
Swiss cheese.
Kosher salami.
We're stacking
this thing up, huh?
Yep.
Homemade corned beef.
That melts in your mouth.
Turkey breast.
Okay.
There's more meat
going on?
This is our braised brisket.
Just a little bit of coleslaw.
Not too much.
Easily four pounds.
I don't know
what to do.
Just bite
the top of it.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, God.
What you need?
Beer? Napkin?
Beach towel?
Got you, man.
I love big sandwiches.
I love hoagies.
But you guys have a whole
different attitude about it.
It's really great.
And I love how you take
that corned beef
and treat it
with all that respect.
That's a real
tasty sandwich.
Good job, brother.
Mom, sandwich up.
Big sloppy mess,
and it's really good.
I happened to run into one
of my buddies Stevo here
who plays in the NFL.
What do you think about
this sandwich, man?
Man, this is great.
There's just so many
different flavors in here.
This, to me, is kind
of a nondescript little place.
You'd just
be walking along,
you'd pass right by it.
Yeah. That's true.
Here at lunchtime, it's packed
and it's quite crowded.
How would you find it?
You'd have to be walking by.
You'd have
to know a local, I guess.
MAN:
Everything's fantastic.
The freshest,
the best, homemade.
JON: Roast pork broccoli rabe
for here.
It's a very savory sandwich.
The gremolata sauce,
it just adds
a really nice touch.
What are we into now, buddy?
This is
our roast pork sandwich.
Okay, this is
pork belly,
so we're into porchetta,
baby.
Okay. I'm gonna scour
the inside of the belly.
This basically is gonna let
some of those seasonings go in.
Flip the pork belly.
Okay.
I'm gonna poke a lot
of holes in this.
Now we're gonna rub it.
First thing, salt and pepper.
Ground and toasted
fennel seed.
I like the fact
that you toasted it.
All right, this
is garlic confit.
This is just garlic
slow-cooked in oil.
Roasted garlic.
This is the juice
and the zest
of one orange, one lime,
and one lemon.
Okay.
I want to get that in everywhere
on this, all right?
Very, very serious
about what he's doing.
Very serious, Guy.
Making a sandwich --
I didn't know he could hear me.
Picked rosemary.
Okay.
Same thing with the thyme?
Yes, sir.
Fresh sage.
Okay.
This is my favorite part.
Pecorino Romano.
Dude, this is like
flavor explosion over here
in hoagie heaven.
So, now we're gonna add
our pork loin,
and then
we're gonna tie the porchetta
so we can roast it off.
All right,
now onion, carrot, celery,
black peppercorn,
star anise,
whole garlic cloves.
Now a little water?
A little bit of water
to create the au jus
Now we're gonna roast
it up, okay?
Four hours and 20 minutes.
Got it.
Then the next day,
we rub the skin
with really good
olive oil, salt, pepper.
And then we blast it
in this pizza oven
at 600, 700 degrees
until we crisp it.
Let it rest for
like 30 minuets,
then we slice it down.
What are we into now?
This is our hazelnut
gremolata sauce.
This right here,
this is basically parsley,
olive oil, salt,
and pepper just blended up.
Scallions.
Hazelnuts,
roasted and crushed.
Okay.
Red onion.
Red wine vinegar.
Roasted jalapeño,
pealed and chopped.
Garlic.
This is so
not under-seasoned.
Orange, lime,
and lemon.
The same
that we put on the pork.
And fried capers.
Voilà.
That's it, man.
[ Spoon clatters ]
[ Laughs ]
That's ridiculous.
Thank you, sir.
Now we got to assemble it,
all right?
Gremolata --
get a nice, even amount.
Got the broccoli rabe in there.
So you got a little bitterness
coming in there.
Yep. Roast pork
in the au jus.
Now take the roll,
and we're gonna slice
that bad boy.
Nice pieces
of sharp provolone.
And that's it, man.
Look at that.
Wow.
Flavortown overload.
Flavors are so big
and so rich.
This sandwich
eats like a meal.
What you offer in that porchetta
sandwich is really generous.
And I don't mean
in the portion size.
I just mean in the effort.
I mean,
it just makes you step back
for a second and go, "Wow."
The flavor
of the pork is phenomenal.
The gremolata sauce just adds
this nutty, hearty flavor to it.
MAN: If I could pick
my last meal,
it would be a large hoagie
from Bub and Pop's.
Everybody talks about this place
with such enthusiasm.
You got to stop in,
and you got to try it.
You killed it.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up in Colorado Springs...
Those fries are gangster.
...an out-of-the-box
burger spot...
Break all the rules.
...where over-the-top
is standard issue.
We're doing it all here
at the Skirted Heifer.
Oh, my God.
That is so good.
So, I'm here in the center
of it all,
right downtown
in Colorado Springs, Colorado,
right across from Acacia Park.
Now, I'm here to check out
a funky, funky burger joint
owned by a local family
that has a name
that you just won't forget.
This is the Skirted Heifer.
I've got the double
build-your-own burger.
These are gourmet burgers.
I can't think
of anything better.
Gobble Gobble
Turkey Burger up.
I've probably gained 10 pounds
since they opened.
FIERI:
That's just since 2014,
when long-time restaurant owners
Kevin and Suzette Megyeri
opened this burger joint
and named it
after their signature item.
Ready for
that skirted heifer.
MAN: Real unique the way
they melt the cheese over it
and make it look
like it has a skirt on it.
How did you learn about it?
By watching your show.
There you go.
FIERI:
But the skirt's just one page
in the playbook around here.
They're very unique with all
the different type of burgers
they come up with.
All right.
Here we go.
There's your Hangover.
It's got cream cheese.
It's got peach wood bacon.
And the Bloody Mary sauce.
It's an excellent burger.
FIERI:
So, what are we making now?
SUZETTE: All right.
We're gonna make
some homemade ketchup.
Why make your own ketchup?
The homemade ketchup
is a base
for a lot
of our homemade sauces.
Okay.
Take some good,
old-fashioned white sugar.
Dissolve it with
a little bit of water.
Okay,
so we go on the flattop.
And then tomato puree.
White vinegar.
Salt.
Garlic.
White pepper.
Okay, how long
will this cook?
About a half-hour.
Can I try this
wild concoction?
I hope you like it.
Very good.
It's very tomato-y.
Not quite as sweet
as processed ketchup.
That's what
you're looking for.
Good.
The Bloody Mary sauce
has everything
that you would put in
your Bloody Mary drink.
I don't put ketchup in my --
except maybe vodka.
And no vodka.
And no --
Oh, there's no vodka in this?
It's been nice.
Thank you very much.
No vodka.
Horseradish.
Worcestershire sauce.
Celery salt.
Mix it all up.
There we go.
You're not light
on the horseradish, are you?
Wow!
All right.
We're gonna make your burger.
We do one-third pound grass-fed,
grass-finished beef.
All the way from Finland.
All the way
from Westcliffe, Colorado.
[ Sizzles ]
Are we gonna season that?
With our focaccia salt.
We've got egg, too.
You want me to keep that on?
Thank you.
Farm egg.
I really appreciate that.
We've got bacon,
homemade focaccia bun,
cream cheese.
Cream cheese
is for the hangover?
How?
Cream cheese bagels.
Everything you'd eat
in the morning on a hangover.
Cap'n Crunch would be on there
in a minute.
All right.
Our Bloody Mary sauce.
Gonna get some fries?
Yeah.
Brown sugar, kosher salt.
A little bit of Cayenne.
That sugar
makes people go "hmm."
Those fries are gangster.
All right. That's a big burger.
There's a lot going on here.
Let me tell you something.
Go ahead.
Have a fry.
[ Laughs ]
Want a bite of the burger?
Come on.
Let's break all the rules.
We're doing it all here
at the Skirted Heifer.
Oh, my God.
That is so good.
Can I get you
something to drink?
Now I'm on your napkin.
[ Laughter ]
Burger's dynamite.
The horseradish
in the tomato sauce
is really what takes it
over-the-top.
The focaccia roll --
spot-on.
The key
to all of this is the crust
that you build on the burger.
Really good.
Great.
I'm so glad you like it.
Really good.
All right, guys.
Your Hangover.
It has, like, that good crisp
from the grill,
but when you bite inside,
it's really juicy and tender.
Meld of flavors that just --
Mmm -- really good.
FIERI: With an attitude
of keeping it local.
You can eat it
with a clear conscience
knowing that the cattle
is well-treated.
Is this some of your beef?
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
That's dynamite.
Our own beef, like,
amazes me every time I eat it.
But when I come here,
it's like triple amazing.
We got a Pueblo Farmer
ready.
The Pueblo Farmer
is my favorite.
Pepper jack cheese,
pueblo chilies,
and fresh-made guacamole.
Okay, what are we
making next?
Guacamole
for our
Pueblo Farmer burger.
Okay.
First, yummy avocados.
Okay, next step?
Some fresh lime juice.
All right.
Chopped jalapeños.
Diced tomatoes.
Onion.
And garlic salt.
Potato masher.
Are we gonna --
Now we're gonna make
your burger.
Okay, fantastic.
I am gonna put
some seasoning on that.
Pepper jack cheese.
[ Whistles ]
Sweet potato fries --
hand-cut, fresh.
Guacamole.
Roasted pueblo chilies.
Skinned?
Colorado is known
for their pueblo chilies.
There you go, Guy.
Pueblo farmer.
Well, I imagine we're both gonna
have a bite of it again.
[ Laughs ]
I love it.
Your guacamole --
very nice, very fresh.
You can't beat chilies.
The grass-fed meat, it's got
a rich mineral flavor to it.
Nice little melt
to the pepper jack.
It's outrageous.
Really dynamite.
Here's your Pueblo Farmer.
Just a tasty burger.
Chiles are like as
they're from my dad's garden.
They're so good.
It's not too hot.
It's just like
the perfect amount of taste.
Really impressed.
It has real rich beef flavor
on a homemade focaccia bun.
All those little points
make this a great burger joint.
You're awesome.
Thanks, Guy.
Keep an eye
on this one.
FIERI: Up next, a local's
Atlantic City hangout...
Spot-on.
...piling up the 'cue...
That's a really
great sandwich.
...and getting
all sophisticated
with the pub grub.
Oh, so now we're just gonna
get down to some Brie.
So, I'm here in
the Chelsea Heights section
of Atlantic City,
right between the boardwalk
and the bay.
And, man, was this area hit hard
by Superstorm Sandy.
A lot of business went out
and never came back,
except for a funky
little joint like this.
Welcome to Vagabond.
Spicy California.
Pick it up.
Food is just awesome here.
Fish and chips.
The local place to go if you're
in the Atlantic City area.
FIERI:
Run by a true local guy...
Hot Mess Mushroom.
Pick it up.
...Atlantic City native
Elvis Cadavid.
I was a bartender here.
Hurricane Sandy hit.
Bang. I'm unemployed, and I got
to figure something out.
So he signed up his childhood
buddy Tom Harris...
Spicy California burger.
...bought the joint,
fixed it up,
and put it back
on the map in 2013.
WOMAN: When Tom and Elvis
reopened it as Vagabond,
instantly, it became a hit.
Seared ahi tuna.
They have so many
different things on the menu
that you can choose from.
Three-way sandwich.
Great combination
between bacon,
pulled pork, and brisket.
Each meat
could be its own sandwich.
So, what are we making?
The mango barbecue sauce
for the three-way sandwich.
We're gonna start off
with brown sugar.
Ketchup. Aqua.
Red wine vinegar.
Worcestershire.
Dry mustard.
Paprika.
Kosher salt.
Black pepper.
Mango puree.
We just bring it
to a boil.
Okay, what are we making now?
The dry rub?
The dry rub
for the pork shoulder.
Brown sugar.
Cajun seasoning.
Very nice.
Oregano.
Garlic powder.
Onion powder.
Cumin.
Cayenne pepper.
That much Cayenne?
Need some heat.
So, that gets mixed together?
Yes, it does.
Before we add the rub,
we do a quick
little marinade.
Okay.
Worcestershire,
liquid smoke.
House rub.
Bay leaves.
And beer.
Now, how long
you gonna let this cook for?
350 for six hours.
What other meat are you
gonna use for that three-way?
Brisket
and candied bacon.
Now, the brisket
gets same rub?
Same rub.
Roasted in the oven?
350 for four hours.
Got it.
And tell me
about the bacon.
Applewood smoked bacon.
I candy is with
a little bit of maple syrup.
Okay.
And fresh-ground pepper.
Go in the oven 450 degrees
for about 15 minutes.
Looking good. All right,
give me a breakdown here.
Start off
with the pulled pork.
Got it.
Next we're gonna add
the brisket.
Bring this up to temp.
Okay.
Add the mango
barbecue sauce.
Locally-made brioche bun.
Yes.
Pork first.
Then the brisket.
Next, the candied bacon.
We're gonna top it off
with a lime slaw.
I like the little stamp
on there.
Our house-made fries.
When I think
about Atlantic City,
I do not think
about barbecue sandwiches.
But I got to tell you,
this would be a home
away from home
for a lot of folks
that want some great barbecue.
Mmm. Smoked,
nice tang, good season.
Making the slaw counterbalancing
with a little acid.
That's a great sandwich.
That's a really great sandwich.
Thank you very much.
Well done.
Barbecue three-way.
The mango barbecue sauce
makes the sandwich.
The maple bacon
that they have on there,
it kind of, like,
takes it to another level.
It's kind of ridiculous.
Caramelized onion burger.
Obviously, you're gonna come
for the food,
but you walk in the door,
and you just love the vibe.
Tommy and Elvis
have done a great job.
FIERI:
Which was no small feat.
Hurricane Sandy
did a ton of damage here.
Three feet underwater
right where you're standing.
So, literally, where we're
standing there's water
this high?
Yes.
MAN:
They put it back together.
Since that,
everybody's been coming here.
And this place
has the best food.
ELVIS:
Tequila shrimp bangers up.
It's lightly breaded shrimp.
MAN: I'm not sure
how Elvis concocts the sauce,
but it's very good.
Why is it tequila banger?
The heat,
the tequila, the bang.
Oh, so like "bang!"
Yes.
Got it. First we're gonna
make the sauce?
Gonna start off
with the mayo.
Thai chili sauce.
Sriracha.
Little sesame oil.
Yes.
Cayenne pepper.
Garlic powder.
Next up?
Tequila.
I love this sauce
more and more.
Adobo seasoning.
And a little aqua.
Quick whisk.
All right.
Let's do the shrimp.
We're gonna dredge the shrimp.
And then we're gonna flash-fry
them for about two minutes.
Spring mix tossed in
a raspberry vinaigrette.
We add the tequila banger sauce
to the shrimp.
So, it's like
a fried shrimp cocktail.
That's just what I need.
Not too much breading.
Little spice.
Little kick
out of that tequila.
And you get
a little salad in it.
It's a great presentation.
Well done, my friend.
Thank you.
ELVIS:
Tequila shrimp bangers.
WOMAN:
They're absolutely bursting
with flavor --
perfect zesty zing.
The chefs here do a great job
at taking normal bar food
and putting their own
unique twist on it.
FIERI: And putting out dishes
you'd normally never
see in a bar.
Turkey apple Brie.
On a cranberry walnut.
A cranberry walnut?
Cranberry walnut.
Okay, when I pull up
to the Vagabond,
I'm not thinking
about any walnut bread.
[ Laughs ]
MAN:
If you're a turkey lover,
you can wait around
for Thanksgiving,
or you can come to Vagabond
and get this sandwich.
FIERI: When we come back.
This better be good.
FIERI: Hey, welcome back
to "Triple D."
Hanging out here
in Atlantic City,
right down the street
from the strip
where my restaurant is
to check out
a guy named Elvis
that owns a joint
called the Vagabond
that was flooded
in Hurricane Sandy.
This place underwater.
It was closed.
MAN:
And they brought it back
and really made
a nice place to hang at.
The best local spot
here in AC, for sure.
Favorite thing on the menu?
Turkey apple Brie,
hands down.
Seriously?
Oh, yeah.
Turkey apple Brie
in the window.
It's like a gourmet grilled
turkey and cheese sandwich.
It's on a nice walnut
cranberry bread.
Smokey pepper jam
brings out the flavor.
It's very good.
The turkey apple Brie.
Oh, so now we're just gonna
get down to some Brie.
Just some Brie, yeah.
So we're gonna make
the smokey pepper jam.
Let's get it.
Raspberry jam.
Sriracha.
You're not mild
on the spice around here.
Very good.
Apple cider vinegar.
Crushed red pepper.
Little chili powder?
Just gonna whisk
this together.
Step one.
What's next?
Turkey breast -- skin on.
And we're gonna start off
with some kosher salt.
Rub it down.
Next?
Fresh pepper.
Little water?
Little aqua.
Cover it up.
In the oven,
350 for four hours.
Got it.
Okay.
So, next
we're gonna start off
with butter,
turkey on the grill.
Okay.
A few slices
of Granny Smith apples.
Brie cheese.
And you're getting
very cosmopolitan on us.
This is my version of
Thanksgiving, I guess,
all year long.
Cranberry walnut toast
off the grill.
Gorgeous.
Top it off
with a little bit
of the smokey pepper jam.
And top that off
with the oven-roasted turkey,
the Granny Smith apples,
and the Brie cheese.
Look at this thing.
It's a Thanksgiving sandwich,
I mean, completely.
You get a lot of Brie
right off the bat.
Apple's still
nice and tender.
Turkey's not dry.
Nice acidity from the jam.
Spot-on.
Turkey apple Brie.
It's delicious.
It really is.
Very creative twist
on a turkey sandwich.
Pick up --
table 61.
It's a great friendly place.
If you're coming to hang out,
you're probably gonna come back.
Show me a little texture,
a little culture
of AC, this is
where you come to find it.
Absolutely.
Nicely done, guys.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to check out
some of the recipes
for the joints we visit,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
You see?
Oh, I've got
a few more tricks.
But I have gloves on,
so...
Oh, I'd give anything
for that.