Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hold on. Hold on.
...we're grabbing
some of the greatest things...
Knockout, man.
Thank you, sir.
...on sliced bread.
Well, that sandwich
is off the hook.
In Modesto, California...
That is ridiculous.
...a traveling
culinary classroom...
This is a road cone
in Flavortown.
...schooling it
with their sandwiches.
Thanks, man.
Spot-on, man. Spot-on.
In Key Largo, Florida...
Whoa, ho-ho.
...a decades-old mainstay...
Aw, you picked the spot.
...casting out
a famous fish dish.
And it started here?
It started right here.
And in Oakland...
Just takes it into
funkalicious.
...a butchery/restaurant
combo...
It's...a masterpiece.
...that's definitely
a cut above.
This is a lights-out game
right now.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here
in the Temescal neighborhood
of Oakland, California,
about a mile from downtown,
to check out a joint, and
we've heard this story before.
It's a husband-and-wife team,
but not just
any husband-and-wife team.
No, they've got a butcher shop,
and not just any butcher shop --
[ Horns honking ]
a butcher shop
inside of a restaurant!
See, these guys love it.
Welcome to Clove and Hoof.
Pork belly in the window.
It's really a neighborhood gem.
All right, guys,
here's your burger.
It's the best meat in Oakland.
It's fantastic.
MAN: I love the fact
that they have a butcher shop
and a place to eat here.
It's complete connection
to the food that you're eating.
FIERI: Credit John Blevins
and Analiesa Gosnell,
a couple with
something uncommon in common.
Both of you
are butchers?
Yes.
Did you guys meet
butchering?
"Hey,
what are you doing tonight?
You want to break down
a side of beef?"
No, we decided we wanted
to learn butchery
a little bit after we met.
FIERI: And the education
paid off.
BLEVINS: Smoked lamb
in the window, table 4.
FIERI: 'Cause they've been
packing them in here
since they opened in 2014.
All the food
is made with so much heart.
FIERI: And a lifetime
of determination.
I've been cooking
for about 15, 20 years.
My hands are
a little bit different.
FIERI: It was not
a butcher accident.
No.
This is how you were born
as a kid.
Yeah.
It's only a disability
if you make it a disability,
and you definitely
have not made it that.
You're working in
probably one
of the most physically
intensive methods of cooking.
John creates these recipes
that are amazing.
Flavors that are familiar to
you, but really highly elevated.
Philly cheesesteak.
The cheesesteak
is a phenomenal sandwich.
The most amazingly tender beef.
And there's something
about the cheese.
It's just perfect.
This is the hip.
Head's up there.
Leg came down here.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
Make sure I give everybody
the lowdown here.
Okay.
I'm removing the top sirloin
for our Philly cheesesteak.
Talking about great butchery,
look at the yield.
I mean,
it's just seamless.
Take that. That'll go
to the butcher shop.
This grind will
become burgers and whatnot.
That's sustainability
right there.
These are gonna go into
a Cryovac bag in the freezer
so it's nice and easy
to slice.
Slice it super-thin.
That's the key
to a great cheesesteak.
Yes, sir.
All right, so, we're
getting ready to make
our beer cheese fondue.
We're just gonna start
with a little bit of olive oil,
throw our onions in there,
raw and pickled jalapeños.
Deglaze this with a little beer.
Let that reduce a little bit.
So, we're gonna make
a little makeshift bain-marie.
Processed cheese
and helping it along
with a little whole milk.
A lot of the flavors
that we do here
are kind of like riffs
on our childhood.
You heard it here.
We're just gonna let that
go for about 10 minutes,
and then we're just gonna
drop it back into
the onion-and-jalapeño
mixture.
So, our version
of a Philly cheesesteak.
Let's do this.
We hit it with a hamster wheel
of butter -- nice, hot grill.
Throw our sirloin,
chop it up nice and fine.
A little
Philly technique there.
A little salt.
We're gonna
hit it with our deglazer.
Which is...?
It's a mixture
of soy, garlic powder,
smoked paprika, and MSG.
Got to have
a little bit in there.
Next up?
Little bit of onion confit,
which we do in butter and oil,
and then marinated mushrooms.
You marinate
the mushrooms in-house.
Also some grilled
trumpet mushrooms.
Then we take a little bit
of our mayonnaise.
Holy moly.
All right.
Your cheese fondue.
Turnips with a little bit
of the mushroom oil.
Turnips?
Just to give it
a little texture.
A little spring mix.
If you're gonna eat the cow,
eat what the cow eats.
And there you have it.
It's...a masterpiece.
First thing's first.
That cheese sauce
is redonkulous.
The mushroom
is outrageous.
Your process
was fantastic.
The meat's perfect.
The roll -- spot-on.
I got to say that if you're
a Philly cheesesteak fan
and you're anywhere
close to Oakland,
you got to
get yourself here.
Mmm.
Table 7, please.
Two cheesesteaks. Let's go!
It's a massive sandwich.
The meat is so tasty,
and the cheese is all creamy.
I love the turnips on top of it,
give a little bit of crunch.
BLEVINS: Bánh mí
in the window.
I come here, I'll get a snack,
and then take things home
for the week.
I can ask the butchers,
"what is this cut of meat?"
We found that people
don't know very much about meat.
They get really intimidated
by butcher shops,
and we want
the opposite to be true.
I like that you know which farms
the animals are coming from.
You know
that they're humanely raised.
And I think
you could taste the difference.
WAITRESS:
Fried chicken.
Our fried chicken
takes it home.
The fried chicken's
better than the cheesesteak?
I -- you know,
it's night and day,
but it's very,
very good.
It totally picks you up. It
says, "I'm a chicken sandwich!"
FIERI: And that's
coming up next.
See you in a bit.
FIERI: Right now, "Triple D" is
hanging in my part of Cali...
BLEVINS:
Pork belly's down.
...at Clove and Hoof
in Oakland....
C&H burger, table 7.
...where
a husband-and-wife team
are running
a butchery/restaurant combo.
How would you describe
what you're coming into here?
Locally sourced,
farm-to-table, fabulous meats.
They don't give you
your run-of-the-mill sandwiches.
Just takes it
into funkalicious?
You betcha.
Fried chicken in the window.
Let's go.
Ah!
The fried chicken sandwich.
You get a little bit
of sweetness,
little bit of crunch,
little bit of savory.
Incredible.
All right, fried chicken.
Take a little salt.
Chicken thighs.
Yeah.
Pack them
into a Cryovac bag
with thyme
and a little bit of garlic.
And then we're gonna slow-cook
these at 155 degrees.
We're gonna sous-vide
the chicken before we fry it?
Correct.
We're looking for optimal,
perfectly cooked meat.
This is a lights-out game
right now.
What are we into now?
We're gonna be making
a savory caramel.
Okay.
So, we're gonna start
with about a quart of sugar,
a pint of water,
and some lemons.
A little bit of black pepper,
star anise,
and cinnamon sticks.
Dig it.
Then we're gonna add
our fish sauce.
I always love in my caramels
a little fish sauce.
So, it adds
a nice savoriness.
When that reaches
the proper consistency,
we're gonna add
our bourbon habanero vinegar
as well as
our Old Bay butter,
which is softened butter,
Old Bay --
[ Record scratches ]
Hold on. Hold on.
Where does Old Bay
come into this?
The nostalgic flavors.
That's something
that I grew up with,
and it wants to go
on chicken.
It tells you this?
Yes.
So, here's our chicken.
Okay.
A little pre-dredge,
which is just flour and salt.
Little bit
of egg and water.
Straight into a post-dredge
which is AP flour,
buzzed-up panko,
garlic powder, Cayenne,
black pepper,
and potato starch.
And then we'll go to the fryer,
flash it, and warm it up,
'cause it's already cooked.
Exactly.
We're gonna toss
in our fish sauce caramel.
The fish sauce caramel.
Then we're gonna dress it
with a little slaw
made with apples, celery,
ginger, cilantro,
hit it with a little bit
of pomegranate
and a little celery leaf.
Looks pretty fancy-dancy
for a fried chicken sandwich.
To call that sandwich
a fried chicken sandwich
is to call a Ferrari
a car.
There's so much
going on.
One, the chicken
is beyond flavorful tender.
I mean, it's --
it's outrageous.
Two, the crunch
is dynamite.
A little slaw
at the end -- genius.
Love the pomegranate,
little crunch when you get it.
But I have to say --
the funk caramel
is the bomb.
Star anise paired up
with the fish sauce,
get a bite of the cinnamon
back there.
It is the funkiest caramel
I've ever had.
That's a sandwich,
man.
And there's
your fried chicken.
Breaded, nice and thick,
perfectly.
Pomegranate seeds are the kicker
in the fish sauce caramel.
The fish sauce caramel
is ridiculous.
Yeah.
I mean,
what are they gonna have,
fish sauce caramel corn
next?
Are we gonna have
a savory ice cream
with fish sauce caramel
and some beef jerky
whipped cream?
Is that's what's coming?
MAN:
He always puts a neat twist.
Every time I come in,
I have to taste something new.
Duck confit in the window.
To see that you two
are taking this on,
not only the mastery
of butchering,
getting the farm to table,
putting it onto the plate,
it's remarkable.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Modesto, California...
Oh, I like the way
this is going.
...a lesson
in Food Truck 101.
Wouldn't you want this guy
as your substitute teacher?
...chalking up
some A-plus pork.
Sandwich is legit.
I'm here in Modesto, California,
in kind of an industrial area
right over on 9th Street
by the railroad tracks
and just a couple blocks
away from the junior college.
I'm here to check out
a food truck, and not
just any food truck.
The chef here -- well, he used
to be a culinary instructor,
and his employees -- well,
they were former students.
So the food's got to be good.
This is the Food Fix truck.
Carnita order's up.
I love the food at this place
because it's different.
Root beer pulled pork.
You've got a lot of different
ingredients in them,
things you wouldn't
find anywhere else.
They're very creative.
FIERI:
And not just in the cooking.
Locally grown chef Hank Olson
had to do some quick thinking
when he added a food truck
to his college teaching gig
back in 2014.
We did
a Kickstarter campaign...
Seriously?
...and raised $20,000.
That's awesome.
How do you describe
the food?
It's kind of dude food,
I guess.
A lot of bacon,
a lot of pork.
Porkstrami pretzel.
I can eat this whole sandwich
daily.
It's just got a burst of flavor.
What are we gonna make?
Pork shoulder.
But I cure it like pastrami
on our homemade pretzel rolls.
We're making the brine
for the porkstrami.
So, this is salt,
brown sugar,
a little bit of curing salt,
black peppercorns,
some nice green coriander,
whole garlic cloves,
cloves, arbol chilies,
mustard seed,
and bay leaves.
So, we'll let that
all steep for how long?
10 minutes.
Bring all that flavor out,
and to cool it down,
you have a little ice water.
And mix that together.
Get the pork butt
and butcher that up.
[ Shing! ]
My pirate sword.
You should wear that
with a sheath.
Basically, just
gonna butterfly it open,
put little cuts
in here,
try to get the brine
way deep in there.
So, we brine it
for how long?
Three days.
Got it.
What...is this?
This is for putting
the netting on the roast.
Like old butcher style?
Yeah.
Take these guys
out of the brine.
This is a road cone
in Flavortown.
No, It's beautiful.
Look at this.
Nice move!
So, we crust this
with green coriander seed,
tons of black pepper.
Oh, I like the way
this is going.
We're gonna slow-roast it.
At what temp?
For the first half-hour, at 375,
get a little crust going,
and then, about another
hour and a half, 325.
Pull it out,
let it cool, slice it up.
We're gonna make
the pretzel rolls.
There's the water,
and then we're gonna add
brown sugar, yeast,
a little bit
of melted butter.
I give this
a little whisk.
Let that bloom.
And then...
All-purpose flour
and a little bit of salt.
We're gonna let it mix
for 6 minutes.
We'll pull it out,
let it proof.
So, now we're gonna
weigh these out to 5.45 ounces,
roll them into a ball.
We'll let them proof
one more time.
And then what are you
brushing them with?
We're brushing them
with baking soda and water,
and an egg wash.
And that's
what gives it nice crust?
The pretzel flavor.
Right.
Cut each roll.
Then they go in the oven
for 350 for roughly 15 minutes.
Smells really good.
So, get those guys
toasting.
And then we have our porkstrami
portioned out.
Just a little mayo.
Little mayo?
And this is
beer mustard.
Oh, put cheese on it,
too.
No party
without Havarti.
And just steam it
real quick.
Gets that cheese
to melt.
That is ridiculous.
Throw the bun
right on there.
Dude.
Mmm.
Just the pork
on its own --
pastrami-esque flavor,
without question.
Now we get into
some pretzel bun.
Anytime I see pretzel
on something, I get after it.
This is light on the inside,
chewy on the outside.
So, the Havarti's
the right choice.
Then
when you combine it...
...with the beer mustard,
sandwich is legit.
Thanks, man.
Spot-on, man. Spot-on.
OLSON:
Porkstrami pretzel!
MAN: The beer mustard is, like,
really what gives it that kick.
You just want to, like,
just keep diving in.
The Havarti cheese --
it's perfect.
Everything's fresh.
It's all local.
FIERI: And straight
out of Hank's textbook.
You were
a culinary instructor.
I'm still
a substitute teacher now.
From there,
he's using his students
to help him
get this truck going.
They get out of school,
they can come here,
learn how to work
on the line.
Pepper jack club.
Wouldn't you want this guy
as your substitute teacher?
He's one of the hardest-working
people I know.
They're always
matching maybe something
that you wouldn't think goes
with something else,
but it turns out
being really good.
FIERI:
Like soda pop and pork butt.
Root beer pulled pork.
I wouldn't know it was root beer
if it wasn't in the name.
Let's get into this.
We're making
a root beer pulled pork.
Start with
big chunks of pork.
So just
regular pork butt.
Season
with salt and pepper.
Then we're gonna
sear it...
golden brown
on each side.
We'll bring it out,
throw it in a hotel pan
and cover it with the root beer,
I assume.
Yep.
Put it in the oven
at 325 for the first hour,
then 275
for the next two hours.
Next up?
Next, we're gonna make
the root beer barbecue sauce.
We have root beer, and then
we're gonna add our ketchup.
Okay,
a little brown sugar.
Ground ginger,
apple cider vinegar,
and salt and black pepper.
And a lot of it.
So once
we mix all these in --
And you'll get
the barbecue consistency.
Once it cools,
it thins up a little bit.
So, this is
the root beer pulled pork,
falling apart --
pork tender.
Go back on the flattop,
put a little crust on it.
Yeah, and just get it
a little shreddy.
Hit it with a little
root beer barbecue sauce.
I put mayonnaise
on everything.
Look at that.
A little bit more
barbecue sauce.
And this is
our sweet-and-sour slaw.
It's an oil-and-vinegar-based
recipe
instead of
your normal mayonnaise.
Mayo. Right. Right.
The slaw is righteous.
Yeah.
You have to have
the contrast --
the sweet root beer
and the tangy slaw.
If you don't have
those two,
you could get
a little too much root beer.
But not a bad thing.
This roll
is working perfectly.
It's so thin and so light,
but creates such a great crust.
That combo, put together,
goes great.
OLSON:
Root beer pulled pork!
It just has so much tenderness
in the meat
that you just want
to go back for more.
It's sweet, a little tangy.
Well,
you call it "dude food,"
but it's just good, simple,
straightforward, creative food.
You are the example
of what people want
a food truck to be --
real deal, a lot of integrity,
a lot of personality.
And you got these young students
working hard with you.
I'm proud of you, buddy.
Thanks, man.
Really proud of you.
Excellent job.
FIERI: Up next
in Key Largo, Florida...
Hey, look.
...a ride
on the water hangout...
Now you're in the know.
...serving up
some signature catch.
Wow. I understand why
this dish is such a hit here.
I'm here in Key Largo, Florida,
at Lake Largo Harbor
to check out a restaurant
that was started
by two pilots in 1950.
And that's not the real story.
The key here is --
Get it? The key?
...is that this place
stakes claim to developing
the most famous fish sandwich
that you'll find in the Keys.
This is Pilot House.
Lobster mac and cheese.
If you don't come here,
you've missed the Keys.
The tuna nachos.
Great food and great atmosphere.
MAN: Dinner, the water,
the boats, the sunset.
I mean, come on.
Can you beat this?
FIERI:
And general manager Mark Charles
is proud to keep
that long-standing vibe going.
The Pilot House has been
the home port for locals
since 1950.
We pride ourselves
on fresh, local seafood.
We're right here at the source,
and they do a wonderful job
of getting from sea to table
very quickly.
FIERI: Thanks to the talents
of executive chef Zach Greene.
It's so varied in the dishes
that they prepare.
And it's so good.
The hogfish macadamia.
Hogfish is one of the best fish
that you can get.
It's prepared
with a mango salsa.
It's wonderful,
something that the chef
does a great job with.
The hogfish
is, like, the local...
Reef-dwelling fish.
So,
what are we gonna make?
This is
the tropical fruit salsa
that'll go on top
of the hogfish.
We're gonna start off
with some mango.
Why, when you say
"tropical fruit salsa,"
do you smile?
'Cause it's tropical, man.
Diced red bell peppers,
diced papaya,
fresh-chopped cilantro,
fresh chopped jalapeño,
sweet chili sauce,
and a dash of salt and pepper.
Mix all that up...
Tropical fruit salsa.
[ Laughs ]
All right.
Here's our fresh hogfish.
We're gonna butterfly
this whole fish open here.
It looks like
you're playing fish origami,
but why is it all still
connected to the fish?
For our plate presentation,
we'll have a skin-on,
butterflied fillet of fish
on the plate
with a cool type of garnish.
Whoa!
We're gonna
salt and pepper that.
That's how hot
you want it?
I want that skin
to crisp up real nice.
I gotcha.
So, we're gonna go into the
convection oven just like that.
That'll go about 6 minutes,
about 425 right now.
425. Way to convection,
as well.
At home, you would want to
put that oven on "clean"
because that's
about the only way
you're gonna get it
that hot.
Who's taking over
the show?
[ Laughs ]
Toasted crushed macadamia nuts
for the macadamia crust.
A little
Japanese bread crumb,
some whole butter,
sprinkle of salt and pepper.
Crush all that stuff
together.
And we'll just throw
a pat of that --
Right on top
of that fish in the oven.
Ah!
Now we're gonna get
our beautiful piece of hogfish,
top that
with a little bit
of our fresh citrus
butter sauce here,
our tropical fruit salsa
right on top of that
and fresh cilantro,
and we are ready
for rock 'n' roll.
All right.
Wow.
I understand why this dish
is such a hit here.
Super-fresh,
prepared great.
Presentation is gorgeous.
I love the butterflying
technique you did.
Nice, bright citrus salsa --
complements it incredibly well.
The crunch
of the macadamia nut.
Mmm!
Knockout, man.
Thank you, sir.
Knockout.
Mmm!
We have the
macadamia encrusted hogfish.
They do it right.
They know exactly
how to cook hogfish here.
Lights-out good.
Amazing.
You picked the spot.
Also sits
on a beautiful marina.
We take the boat here
all the time.
It's just a wonderful experience
here in the Keys.
FIERI: Which includes
a Keys culinary classic.
It's been around since the '70s.
Here's the
Harvey fish sandwich.
Oh, thank you.
Harvey was a fish cutter
here at the pilot house.
To this day,
there's Harvey's fish sandwiches
in almost every menu
up and down everywhere.
No!
And it started here?
It started right here
at the Pilot House.
Now you're in the know.
I love the fish Harvey.
I love it.
It's basically
a grilled cheese sandwich
that they've infused
with fresh local fish.
So, what fish
do we have here?
Fresh black grouper,
about 7-ounce portions.
We've got
some seasoned flour.
What's it seasoned with?
A little Bay seasoning
and salt and pepper. That's it.
Lightly egg-washed.
Little panko to it.
Into the deep fryer
with that, 350 degrees,
It takes
about 7 minutes.
So, we've got
our grilled cheese sandwich.
Wheat bread, huh?
Whole wheat,
sliced American cheese.
Sliced tomato,
we're gonna stick on here
just to warm them up.
Top that
with our fried grouper.
Some of our house-made
tartar sauce -- top that.
And there's your world-famous
Harvey's fish sandwich.
So if you want to get it
at the place it started,
this is where you go.
Mmm!
First, the fish is great.
Really nice and moist.
I mean, there's great flavor
in that black grouper.
Got a great toast
on the bread.
Spot-on
with the whole-wheat move.
The tartar sauce
definitely plays its piece,
but it's the processed cheese
and the tomato.
Yes.
I can understand
why the sandwich is so popular.
This is up in the best fried
fish sandwich I've ever had.
GREENE: Harvey fish sandwich
in the window.
The local flavor
of the fish, you can't beat.
I didn't know you could put
cheese on a fish sandwich.
It's delightful.
FIERI: Whether Harvey himself
knew it became famous,
there have been a lot
of different owners,
so no one really knows.
I want someone
to send me a Twitter
or go on Facebook
if they know any more story
about Harvey.
I'd like to hear it.
Yeah.
'Cause that sandwich
is off the hook.
Mmm!
Hey, look.
So, was this a great road trip
or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners,
Drive-ins, and Dives."
When you say "dude food"
and you're saying,
"I'm making a porkstrami
on a pretzel bun,"
and I'm like,
"All right" --
[ Train horn blows ]
My train's here.
Got to go.
[ Laughs ]
[ Train horn blows ]