Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Clicks tongue ]
...it's full-on meat madness...
Get out of here.
...with some crazy cuts
to choose from.
It's outrageous.
In Baltimore...
Look at that!
A chef mixing
it up with pork belly...
Ah, that's gonna be good.
...while sliding out
the bomb wild boar.
It's no namby-pamby slider
right there.
In Washington, D.C....
Oh, my gosh.
...a spot carving
up lights-out pastrami...
I want to live
by this place.
...and rolling' out
righteous chorizo.
Man, when you say "chorizo,"
you mean chorizo.
Whoa.
Plus, a Jamaican joint
in Colorado Springs...
I can hear reggae
in the background.
...Where the jerk chicken
is king...
This is how you do it.
...and the goat
is something to scream about.
That's good!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
So you're in a town
that you're not from
and you're here to see a game.
And after the game,
where do you go?
Well,
if you happen to be in Baltimore
and you're at Camden Yards,
I got one for ya.
Three blocks north, you'll find
a funky little place.
They say they're a beer bar,
but they forget to mention
they got a scratch-made kitchen.
This is Alewife.
A blue catfish taco
in the window.
I got to say it's one of the
most unique and creative places
I've ever been.
WAITRESS: Smoked burger.
Oh, yeah.
WOMAN: I've tried things
that I never thought
I would have tried before.
The food is unbelievable.
FIERI: That's because
owner Bryan Palombo
knew he needed an elevated menu
to match their serious selection
of over 90 brews.
And a little luck led him
to Executive Chef Chad Wells
when he opened in 2010.
PALOMBO: He had just moved
back to Baltimore.
He needed a gig,
and we needed a chef.
We met.
We clicked real quick.
WOMAN: When Chad's here
with his creativity,
it's gonna be delicious
no matter what I get.
Pork belly mac and cheese fries.
Duck fat fries --
awesome.
You can't go wrong
with pork belly.
There's just so many
wonderful flavors
that work together great.
Pork belly...
Pork belly.
...mac and cheese.
Collard greens.
Duck fat fries.
This is pork belly.
We're gonna cube it all up
and then sear it in a pan.
Got it.
Kosher salt.
And ground black pepper.
Now hit 'em with...
Chicken stock first.
Okay.
Plus some pale ale.
And barbecue sauce that we
make with some Citra hops.
Citra hops.
This is gonna cook
for three to five hours.
Dig it.
So this is
the collard greens.
Get it.
And a little bit of oil,
some diced onion, bacon.
Got it.
Add the greens to it.
Love greens.
Salt, apple cider vinegar,
a lot of chicken stock.
Oh, it's gonna be good.
So let this work
for a few hours, super tender?
Yes, sir.
That's all she wrote.
Next up, we're gonna bang
out this cheese sauce.
Let's start with
some butter.
This is Gruyère.
And then right behind that,
Palmyra cheddar.
This is a local
Maryland cheddar.
Stir it around
and wait for it to melt.
And then we're gonna add
our flour, vegetable stock.
And then we're gonna hit it
with the immersion blender.
While I'm mixing it, I'm gonna
add some heavy whipping cream.
Start pouring that
directly in.
We're gonna hit it
with some granulated garlic,
Parmesan cheese,
kosher salt.
Let this go
for 30 minutes.
Next up -- just gonna add some
noodles to our cheese sauce.
Fire it up.
Start with
some duck fat fries,
our collard greens,
our mac and cheese.
Rotini.
Holds the cheese better.
Best part -- We seared some
of our pork belly, hit it
with more hot barbecue, get
a little bit of texture on it.
Got it.
Right on top.
Look at that.
Well, this is
a very composed dish.
It has a lot
of culinary merit.
The greens are spot-on.
The rotini works perfect.
Like, the cheese choice
and a little pork belly on top.
The barbecue sauce
isn't overpowering.
And it eats
like a well-balanced meal.
And duck fat fries?
Get out of here.
If you're gonna eat a fry,
eat one cooked in duck fat.
Absolutely.
Got a pork belly fry
in the window.
MAN: It was sort of amazing
to discover
all of the layers
that existed in it.
Duck fat fries, honestly,
I dream about them.
MAN:
Chad -- always been very willing
to push boundaries,
incorporate ingredients
people do not normally use.
FIERI:
Like finding a way to cook off
an invasive species taking over
the Maryland ecosystem.
Snake head in the window.
You have
got to be kidding me.
It looks horrible.
They don't taste like they look.
They're delicious.
But if snake head
isn't your thing,
Chad's got another tasty trick
up his sleeve -- wild boar.
We have a feral hog problem
in the United States.
I have 'em on my ranch.
I know about feral hogs.
Yep.
Well, you got -- You can eat
good whenever you want, then.
So you're really introducing
real-deal wild boar?
Yes.
Wild boar slider in the window.
I like the wild boar.
It's got a lot more flavor
than your regular ol'
ground pork product.
The boar sliders
are always delicious.
It's sort of that Southeast
Asian kind of flair.
Okay, so here's the ground
wild boar?
Yes, sir.
So we're just gonna start
with ginger,
lot of kosher salt.
Dig it.
Some fresh garlic cloves,
chopped chives, sesame oil.
All right.
So we'll make up a little paste?
Yep.
We'll mix this right
into this ground boar.
What size
you gonna form into?
About 3-ounce patties.
And then
they go right on the grill.
Let's do it.
So we start
with this salad.
It goes on top of each one.
Okay.
Some daikon sprouts,
pickled carrots,
ginger dressing.
Oh, yeah.
Sriracha aioli on the buns.
A grilled boar slider.
That's no namby-pamby slider
right there.
Oh, no.
We don't play around in here.
The salad on top, little
bit more of the Sriracha aioli.
And that's all she wrote.
Yep.
The combination was built
to go together.
That boar meat --
rich, dense, big flavor.
It cut with the acid
of the pickled veg.
Really nice, bright ginger,
little bit
of that daikon sprout.
And then you fortify it
with that Sriracha mayo
so you get a little bit
of that spice coming through.
Really a great way
to use the wild boar.
I like the look.
I like the creativity.
That's great, man.
Wild boar sliders.
So, of course, when I'm
in a beer hall in Baltimore,
who do I run into?
Bob from Chaps Pit Beef
and Sophia from Sip & Bite.
Wild boar slider --
Break this down for me.
I like everything about it.
I love the pickled vegetables.
I like the dressing on it.
Nice ambiance
and friendly faces.
So as two of the "Triple D"
originals in Baltimore, you
are absolutely voting these guys
in to be on the "Triple D" team?
Absolutely.
The O.G.s have convened.
There ya have it.
Alewife is my go-to place.
This is where I love to be.
Good, man. Like the place.
It's fun.
Thank you.
[ Clicks tongue ]
FIERI: Coming up
in Washington, D.C....
Big playground.
...A joint cranking
up deli creations...
Wow.
...including a meaty
Moroccan flavor fest.
Mega flavor.
I mean, dude, you
touched the spectrum of flavors.
So I've got a little
"Triple D" travel tip for ya.
The next time you're here
in D.C.
visiting the FBI building --
I know nobody there --
or you're stopping
by the U.S. Attorney's Office --
I'm not exactly sure
where that is --
or you're catching
a Wizards game, well,
you got to stop by this little,
we'll call it
a carnivore compound,
where this couple
is scratch-making everything.
This is the Carving Room.
Steak and egg burger.
I've actually eaten here more
than I've eaten at my own house.
Pastrami sandwich
with Israeli salad.
It's not just a meal.
It's an experience.
Moroccan burger plate.
You can tell that there's so
much love and history and family
that goes into everything
that they make.
FIERI: It all started
with owner Oded Weizmann's
Jewish-Moroccan mom.
Everything at home
was made from scratch.
You open the fridge,
it was just produce and meats,
and if you wanted something,
it had to be made.
Which is still going
on at the dream joint
he opened with business and life
partner Rachel Steiman in 2013.
Everything's made in-house?
Everything, from scratch.
Pastrami poblano
in the window.
I've been all around the world,
and I always search out
a pastrami.
This one right
here is right on-point.
All right, boss.
That's a huge brisket.
WEIZMANN: Yeah.
We trim the fat
down to about 1/4 inch.
Okay.
Take some cracked coriander.
Black pepper.
Ground cloves,
bay leaves, ground,
some sugar.
Okay.
Mix that up.
That's ready to roll.
So you're gonna lay down
the curing salt?
Yep.
Now the rub.
And this is just as heavy
as you can get it on?
Yep.
This is the flavor. We're gonna
let it sit for nine days.
Okay.
It's been rinsed, cured.
Now we're gonna
give it one more rub.
And we're gonna
mix two to one.
Two parts black pepper
in weight
to one part ground coriander
to weight.
That's right.
And just lay it on there
thick.
Don't hold back.
You want a nice crust
when you cut into it.
All right.
This is ready to roll.
And throw it in the oven,
low and slow.
215 all night long.
Amen.
And what are we making
now?
Got our homemade mayo, which is
the base for our chipotle mayo.
We're gonna add some chipotles
in adobo sauce,
all chopped up, fresh garlic,
ancho chili powder.
Okay.
Fresh lime juice.
Let this set up for a little bit
before we use it?
That's right.
You ready?
Hit it.
So we're gonna go
against the grain.
Oh, my gosh.
Gonna chunk it up.
Okay.
Now, what happens?
Throw it on the flattop,
get it a little crispy.
Okay.
Roasted poblano.
Put it on top.
Provolone.
And serve this on?
Ciabatta.
So that's our
chipotle mayo.
So what do we have here?
That's the Moroccan carrot
salad.
Ah, that's good.
Little fresh cilantro
on top.
All right.
There ya go.
Mmm.
Big, rich sandwich
but not heavy.
Pepper and coriander
all day.
The combos all work great.
Lot of spice coming
through that chipotle mayo,
that and the poblano.
You gonna want some heat
on a sandwich,
this is yours.
Mmm.
Scratch-made.
Can't beat it.
Nice job.
Thanks.
Appreciate it.
Tons of flavor in that.
Yeah.
WAITRESS: Pastrami poblano
with carrot salad.
This is my favorite sandwich.
I haven't had its equal.
So much flavor,
and nobody does it like they do.
See our turkey burger
in the window.
It's call the Carving Room
for a reason.
You can actually see
them carving fresh meat
when you walk in.
WOMAN:
They've got a test kitchen,
so they always say, "Oh,
you've got to try something
I've just made.
I know you're gonna love it."
Big playground.
Absolutely. Every day, we kind
of roll different stuff out.
I want to live
by this place.
MAN: Everything
on the menu is original,
and you're not gonna find it
at your typical restaurant.
FIERI: Especially true
with this Moroccan tradition.
One cigar sampler.
The cigars
are a family recipe.
MAN: It's sort of like a wrapped
egg roll, except the wrapping
is much lighter and flakier.
And the filling is spiced meat.
What are we into now?
Making the chorizo
for the chorizo cigars.
Cigars.
Yeah.
Let's do it.
Got some cilantro,
chopped onion, fresh garlic.
Okay.
Smoked paprika,
Hungarian paprika,
ancho chili.
Very nice.
Got some cloves,
allspice.
Okay.
Chili flakes,
ground coriander.
Okay.
Toasted cumin seeds.
Very nice.
Oregano.
Cinnamon-a-min-a-min-a-min.
Cinnamon, kosher salt.
Okay.
Excellent.
Thank you.
Butcher's grind pepper.
All right.
Chorizo mix made.
Right.
Now pork butt time?
Yep.
Mix it with the seasonings.
If you don't have
pepper spray
walking alone at night
by yourself,
carry a handful of that.
Throw it into the freezer,
45 minutes,
get it super cold.
Got it.
And we'll grind it up.
After we come
out of the grinder?
Cook it up a little bit
on the flattop.
Then, we're gonna
let it cool.
Very nice.
And we got
our cigar wrapper.
Now, how many different kinds
do you make?
Three different kinds.
We got
our Moroccan-spiced ground beef,
the chorizo, which we made,
and then the corned beef hash.
Real simple fold.
Little bit of egg white.
Just to seal the edge.
Then we fry 'em up.
These are the Moroccan-spiced
ground beef cigars...
Nice presentation.
Yes.
And chorizo cigars with the
roasted poblano tomato salsa.
And the last
is the corned beef hash cigars
with our house-made Russian.
So this is Moroccan?
Yep.
Wow.
The chorizo that we made...
Chorizo.
Man, when you say "chorizo,"
you mean chorizo.
Whoa.
Mega flavor.
I mean, dude, you
touched the spectrum of flavors.
Just enough meat,
just enough wrap.
The dipping sauces all pair
nicely.
There's all kinds
of flavor.
Cigar sampler for ya.
It's like having
a Moroccan experience in D.C.
MAN: You get a great crunch.
And then you get hit with the
spice afterwards of the meat.
Order, please,
sweet and savory.
There's no place I'd rather be
to have a great meal.
It's so much more than just a
Moroccan menu or a Jewish deli.
I love your attention to detail.
I love your appreciation.
Thanks.
You're doing great.
Congrats.
Appreciate it.
Lights out.
FIERI:
Up next in Colorado Springs...
Time to eat.
...welcome to Jamaica, man.
This is so tender,
so flavorful.
And legit island recipes.
Mmm, mmm, mmm!
So I got a great
"Triple D" story for ya.
Got this married couple.
The wife is in the military,
and they travel from Nebraska
to the Netherlands
to Ohio to Maine.
And the whole time,
they want great Jamaican food.
They can't find any,
so they start to make their own.
And their friends
say, "You know what?
Someday, you guys should open
your own restaurant."
After they get stationed here
in Colorado Springs,
they do just that.
This is Spice Island Grill.
How long on the festival bread,
on the plantains?
Ah, I got it three minutes.
Three minutes.
One bite,
and I'm on island time.
Jerk pork up.
The food is amazing
every time.
FIERI: That's 'cause Claudette
and Glenroy Hutchinson
know Jamaican food.
They grew up on it,
and when their families
immigrated to the States,
they brought their recipes
with them everywhere they went.
You were in the military?
I was in the military.
Every place you go, you're
not finding Jamaican food,
so you're cooking
your own Jamaican food.
We're cooking
our own Jamaican food.
And then your friends
are coming around,
trying your Jamaican food.
Yes.
FIERI:
And that experience paid off
when they opened this joint
in 2011.
Curry goat, table five.
Curry is a big part
of Jamaican dishes.
Okay.
Here's your curry goat.
I cannot think of anywhere else
in Colorado Springs
that you can get curry goat.
So this is a piece of goat.
FIERI:
Row, row, row your goat.
We cook ours with the bone.
That's where all the flavor is.
So take as much of the --
of the meat you can off,
but we definitely like
to keep some bone in.
You want me
to finish that goat?
Yes, please.
I got to step back.
We got goat.
Make sure
I got all my fingers.
We gonna add some vinegar,
add some water,
get all this muskiness off
and all that stuff.
Now it's time
to cook it down.
Okay.
We're gonna add some oil
to the pot.
These pots came all the way
from Jamaica.
I couldn't tell.
Grandma brought 'em
from Jamaica.
[ Sizzling ]
All right.
Add some seasoned salt.
So we let that sear off
for a little bit.
Then, I'm gonna
add a little water.
We're gonna let this cook
for 30 minutes.
Okay. Next up?
We add some oil...
To another one
of those new pots.
...to another pot,
to another pot.
Right.
The garlic, the ginger.
Mix together there.
And then we're gonna
add the curry powder.
This is Jamaican curry.
See how yellow it is?
We like to let
it fry up a little,
and we get the aroma going.
Take our cooked goat.
We just throw it
in there with --
Everybody in the pool.
Like so.
You hear it?
You have to
hear that sizzle.
Look at that.
Oh, smells so good!
Then, we start adding
everything else --
green onions --
I love green onions.
fresh green thyme, onions,
and a lot of green peppers.
Last but not least,
the potatoes.
And 90 minutes later,
we're ready to rock?
Now we're making
rice and peas.
I've had rice and peas.
I've been to Jamaica.
And you had the peas?
Can't you tell 'cause of my hair
I've been to Jamaica?
Oh, yeah.
Ya, man.
It's almost there.
So we use...
Kidney beans.
Yes.
We call everything peas.
Peas, right.
We don't have beans.
So we have some water
boiling.
Add kidney beans.
We add coconut milk.
Nice, coconut-y flavor.
Coconut-y flavor.
Then we add fresh thyme, fresh
green onions, seasoned salt
and then our special red
seasoning to help the redness.
We'll stir this up.
And then
the garlic will go in.
And once that's melted
and boiling, we add the rice.
We'll cover that, let that
cook down for about 30 minutes.
And that's the peas and rice.
They go with the curry goat.
Yes.
And our goat's finished,
and we're ready to serve.
Nice, good sauce
and some potatoes and mix
of everything in there.
So we like to add
some extra sauce on the side,
the rice and peas.
Then we add the sautéed
cabbage, peppers,
onions, and carrots.
Time to eat!
What do you think?
Mmm. Wow.
I'm telling you right now,
this is so tender, so flavorful.
This has got a kiss
of the curry,
little kiss of the thyme.
That is spot-on, 'cause
all that flavor coming out of
those bones into that stock.
Yeah,
if your teeth are strong enough,
you can chew the bone up.
Dr. Latham
does not allow me to...
Chew bones?
No. Not after what
we've been through.
Is that right, Gary?
I like this little cabbage
kicker here.
You know what I think
is interesting about the rice
and peas is that you could only
have so much meat.
And so the rice and peas had
to be a really nice filler,
and that's really what carried
the families through.
Right.
Mmm!
Mmm, mmm, mmm!
That's good!
Curry goat with rice and peas
and cabbage, table 12.
It's kind of a mellower meat.
It's not gamy at all.
It's the perfect intensity
for curry.
Well, it is wonderful,
wonderful.
And I heard they got
a little music thing
going on, too.
Oh, yes.
Polka bands or something?
Oh, no. Reggae band.
Reggae.
Reggae. Polka, reggae?
Polka? [ Chuckles ]
You feel like you're
on vacation right
when you walk in the door.
So we're hanging out
at Spice Island Grill
in Colorado Springs,
Colorado.
When we come back,
we're gonna make...
I don't care what we make.
It's gonna be dynamite.
See ya in a bit.
Ah.
See that?
It's a look of just having
three plates of goat.
We're here at
Spice Island Grill
in Colorado Springs,
Colorado.
She's the one to blame
for this.
What are we doing next?
If you say "Jamaica,"
what do you think of, right?
Bob Marley.
No, food.
Allspice.
Never mind.
Red beans and rice.
You think jerk chicken!
Jerk chicken, table six.
The jerk chicken
is an amazing mixture
of spices and flavors.
It's incredible.
It's more flavorful than spice,
to me.
Let's get after it.
Okay.
So I have some
red cayenne pepper.
You know,
you can't have too much pepper.
Some paprika, just regular salt,
cumin,
or "cuhmin,"
we call it in Jamaica.
This is our secret ingredient --
some ground coffee.
Mix it all together.
We use this as our dry rub.
That's four times the amount
of cayenne to anything else.
It's jerk.
It has to start with spice.
Could we just crumble up Rolaids
and throw 'em in there now?
You won't need the Rolaids
when we add the wet stuff to it.
It just all balances out.
So next,
we make our marinade.
It's gonna be like a paste.
In a blender, we add garlic,
oil, vinegar, thyme, fresh,
and lots
of green onions
and ginger.
There ya go.
Okay, next up...
Chicken leg quarters.
We brush this
with vinegar.
Then, we're gonna
add the red seasonings.
Get it all
underneath the skin.
I guess it takes two people
to do this.
Yeah, it goes a little
bit faster when we
do it this way, huh?
We add our...
The blend up, yeah.
So this is there
the flavor comes from.
So this is some -- a jerk
predone marinade from Jamaica
to add a little bit
of extra Jamaica to this.
And the oil,
we just kind of put
a little bit on it to kind
of keep it moist on the grill.
All right.
Next up -- the grill.
Look at those beauties!
Oh, my goodness!
If I ate meat,
it would have been on.
You don't eat meat?
I don't eat meat.
I do taste it 'cause,
you know, I have to.
Right.
Chop it up,
put that chicken up there.
It's a number-one hit
right here.
Everybody come
for the jerk chicken.
We get a little sauce.
What is it?
Jerk marinade, little bit
of spices and some veggies.
And then
we got some plantains.
Voilà.
So I've had a lot
of jerk chicken.
Everybody has their own style.
This is how you do it.
It's outrageous.
Mmm.
Tremendous layers of flavor.
Just look at all the --
how the fat is cooked
out of the skin
and the skin's
nice and crispy
and the chicken
is just succulent
and all the spices
and the seasoning.
And then it's got
all the marinade on it.
He's trying to tempt me,
no, no!
And then
when you cook it down,
you get
a little caramelization.
And then
you dip it into that sauce.
you just come right over this.
Oh!
I'm not looking!
Mmm!
Listen. Listen.
I can hear reggae
in the background.
Jerk chicken up!
As a Jamaican,
I can speak to the authenticity.
There's just a combustion
of flavors.
A combustion.
It's just awesome.
It takes you
out of Colorado Springs
and into a Jamaican culture.
Blessing.
Ever live it,
ever faithful, ever sure.
Awesome job.
Aw, thank you.
So that's it for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
I'm back eating again!
I'm trying to wrap the show.
Good night!
It's ridiculous!
I've got to go!
They keep
sucking me back in!
See ya next week.
I'm going to the gym.