Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, & dives.
This trip...
Agh!
We're crossing the country.
It's a great idea.
To get a taste of the world.
This is really
gonna be the bomb.
In San Francisco.
Yes!
A joint cranking out
the Cuban --
Handmade, scratch-made.
and platefuls of Puerto Rico.
Let me take 18 more bites
and check this out.
In Key Largo --
Living on the edge.
an island of Italian
I'm gonna die.
served up
with an oldschool spin.
Like little tears
of angels.
And in Stockton, California --
This is crazy-good!
a Laotian food truck
My mouth just went
into total flooding.
revving up
the fiery favorites.
Oh, that's hot!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
& Dives."
♪♪
So, back in the day, when we
first started "Triple D,"
if you woulda told me that
I was gonna be driving around
to random parking lots, looking
for food trucks, I woulda said,
"You are crazy."
All right.
You are crazy because that's
exactly what I'm doing.
I'm here
in Stockton, California,
looking for a first on
"Triple D,"
and that's a food truck
serving up Laotian street food.
This is Green Papaya.
But there's a line?
♪♪
Love Green Papaya food truck.
Best food around.
-Hello!
What can I get for you?
-It's top-notch.
I got nam khao at the window.
Not a lot of places
like this.
Not a lot
of Laotian food trucks,
not in my travels, at least.
Which is what drove
Mony Vangsoulatda
into the biz in 2013.
I said, "Well, nobody's
done Thai or Lao food.
I'm gonna do it!"
-There we go.
-From there on.
-How do you describe Lao food?
It's spicy, sour, bitter.
Order for kham tien.
The kham tien
is a very common dish
that we eat,
almost like Vietnamese pho.
It's spicier and much more sour,
versus the Vietnamese pho.
GUY: What're we
gonna make first?
We're gonna do
the chicken broth.
So we have water,
chicken soup base,
salt, sugar,
just those three.
And then, we're gonna put
our chicken in.
So while that is cooking,
we're gonna go
and make our noodles.
People buy noodles,
you know.
Where do you buy
your noodles from?
G&G Market, one of
my favorite grocery stores,
and also has the greatest
Asian food selection.
-Rice flour, tapioca starch.
-Okay.
So I'm gonna pour
my hot water in there.
And your mom would do this all
the time when you were a kid?
I would have to
wake up early, early,
before I go to school,
to help her.
The things that I find
in food trucks:
making her own noodles.
-It's more fresh.
Want me to sprinkle
a little down for ya?
Yes.
You're doing good!
You probably done this
a lot of times,
this kind of thing.
-I've never made noodles
in a truck
with a girl named Mony.
It feels like a giant
marshmallow.
That's gonna be a nice,
big, thick noodle, huh?
-Yes.
-So noodles are done. Okay.
We are going to make the
garlic oil for the soup.
As a garnish?
-Yes.
So we're gonna heat up
some oil, garlic.
We're gonna
make it brown.
Got it.
This is ground
Thai chili pepper.
We're gonna put
paprika in there,
for the color.
Sugar.
And then, that's it.
We turn the heat off.
And then, we're gonna add
our garlic back in.
We're just gonna
let it cool.
Now, we're going to
peel our chicken,
just big chunks.
-Okay.
So, now, we're going to
make our noodles.
This is just that simple broth
that we cooked the chicken in.
Waiting for the water
to boil.
Don't watch it, then.
"A watched pot never boils."
-Okay, I'm not.
-You never heard that?
No.
Don't look at it.
You're looking at it.
-I saw you. I saw you.
-I saw you look at it.
-No.
-Don't look at it.
-I saw you staring.
I'm checking.
You just looked at it.
It was nice knowing ya.
-[Laughs]
So here we go.
Okay. My mouth just went
into total flooding.
Now, we're gonna add
the chicken.
Look like
it's almost ready.
I'm not gonna look
at it.
Okay.
Very hot.
I love chicken noodle
soup, so.
-Yeah?
-Especially with fresh noodles.
Little bit of cilantro,
scallion,
and then garlic.
There we go.
Chili oil
and lime juice.
There you have it.
Mix it all up.
All the flavor in there.
[laughing]
It's very, very hot.
Yeah, I can see that.
It's like a volcano.
Mmm. Superflavorful.
Definitely getting some
of that garlic,
little bit of spice.
Love the acid from the lime
getting in there.
The chicken's moist, gives
that little creaminess to it.
Mmm! Oh.
These noodles got some texture
and some bite and some girth.
This is crazy-good!
Ohhh!
Without question:
top 3 best Asian soups
I've ever had in my life.
It has a very authentic
taste to the soup,
just like with my mom.
This is one of my longtime
college buddies.
Loren, how's the soup?
-Broth is outstanding.
Let's see you try to eat that.
[Laughter]
It's gonna be so hot,
you're gonna burn your mouth.
Whoo-hoo!
This is delicious.
Something that you can't
get anywhere else.
I'm in Stockton, California,
in a random parking lot,
hanging out with a girl
named Mony
that has a trailer
called the Green Papaya,
blowing my mind
with outrageous
chicken noodle soup Asian-style
and, next, Green Papaya salad.
You gotta come back.
♪♪
So welcome back.
"Triple D"
is here in Stockton,
California, hanging
out at the Green
Papaya food truck
with the crazy Mony.
I know what's coming.
We're gonna make
green papaya salad.
Aaaaaaah!
The Green Papaya salad
is just fire.
[laughs] That's the one
word to describe it.
I got a spicy
Thai papaya salad.
It's one of my favorites
on the menu,
something I get every time.
This is a papaya.
It has to be green
and firm.
This is really
gonna be the bomb.
If you've never had
green papaya salad,
just get in a plane.
Forrest Gump it,
run across country.
Well, I'm gonna have you
hold this for me.
That's great.
-How many pepper you want?
How many Thai chili?
-I trust what you say.
We'll go with three.
Then, we're gonna
put in our sugar.
And then, we're gonna put
a little pinch
so that juice doesn't
splatter everywhere.
We're gonna smash this up,
get all the papaya juice out.
Don't look at it.
The chili's gonna get
into your eyes.
Then, we're gonna add
the peanut.
Dry-roasted but not salted?
-Yes. And dried shrimp.
Dried shrimp are the kicker.
Tomatoes, fish sauce,
lime juice.
Mix it up a little bit.
Put the papaya in.
We're gonna mix it all up.
Pour into.
Plate it right here.
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
Bit of cabbage for you.
♪♪
Oh!
Oh, that's hot!
Be right back.
Ah!
[echoing] Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
Do you have tears?
No, 'cause they evaporated
as it came outta my face.
Holy moly.
It's so good.
It was worth it.
I'd do it again.
It's such a good kick.
It's perfect.
And I love mine extra sour
and extra spicy.
I know this one person
that had it real spicy one time.
Mouth is still on fire.
Whenever I see them online,
it's like, "Oh,
you're gonna be
in the area.
Okay, I'm gonna
go get some food."
MONY: Got a order
of nam khao here ready.
The nam khao
is a different version
of your typical fried rice.
It's a lot crunchier.
It's a really interesting
dish, really, really good.
We're gonna make the rice
ball for the nam khao.
Cooled jasmine rice.
So we're gonna put
red curry paste.
Okay.
-Sugar.
Onions that
we chopped already.
Breaded coconut.
Not sweetened or anything?
-Nope.
Chicken base soup
right here.
Salt.
Oyster sauce.
That little drop.
-That's all we need.
I have one egg here.
And form it into balls.
And then what're we gonna do
with the balls?
-We're gonna deep-fry them,
for about 10 minutes.
10 minutes?
-Yes.
Now we're gonna break 'em up?
Yeah, we're gonna make,
like, a salad.
And we're gonna add
some pork skin,
been boiled, sliced.
Didn't see that coming.
-This is the Lao nam.
It's the cured pork,
fermented cured pork.
I love fermented pork.
A little bit
of sugar here.
And then lime juice,
cilantro,
and a little bit
peanuts.
Now the scallion.
Put 'em all together.
And we're ready to put 'em
in the plate for you.
Top it off with a little
bit of ginger, mint.
We're going to make it
like a lettuce wrap.
Ahhh!
It's a long process.
Mmm.
A lot going on in there.
I just got a little
hit of ginger.
I got a little bit
of the red chili.
I got a little
bit of the curry.
Now, I just got some
of the salty pork.
I got the sweetness
of the pork skin.
The whole while,
I'm getting a crunchy rice.
This is texture city.
-That's our nam khao.
You are awesome.
Nam khao!
You get the sweet, the sour,
the little spice from the chili.
You have anything
like that before?
No, I haven't, and they're
very delicious.
It is amazing,
how much flavor
they can get
outta that little trailer.
This is the place to go.
Outrageous.
Very impressed.
-Thank you.
-Wow!
Up next...
in San Francisco --
All right.
Let's do it.
a local Latin landmark.
There you go. There we go.
-There we go.
Dishing out one
of my all-time favorites.
That's really good mofongo.
-Thank you very much.
♪♪
So I'm here in San Fran,
in the Mission District.
Everybody know
the Mission District.
It's a very eclectic,
diverse neighborhood,
so I'm not surprised
to know that there is
a funky little joint serving up
two of my favorites.
That's right, Cuban food
and Puerto Rican food.
Mofongo.
You know I love mofongo!
This is El Nuevo Frutilandia.
♪♪
I have a chili relleno
here for you.
The flavors are amazing.
We got a Cuban sandwich
coming out.
It's a blend of Puerto Rican
and Cuban culture.
GUY: A mashup owners
Rafael Frias and Tyrisha Neblett
embraced when they bought
this joint back in 2012.
You're Mexican?
-Yes.
How did you learn how to cook
Cuban and Puerto Rican food?
Well, the recipes
have been passed on
from the previous owner
and previous owner
before that.
Like this Cubano classic.
Ropa vieja.
The meat is really tender,
kinda falls apart in your mouth.
It's like cooked
to perfection.
We're gonna make
a ropa vieja.
Ohhhh.
-Okay?
"The old, torn clothes"?
-That's right.
We got some
chuck roll here.
We're gonna braise it
with a little olive oil.
Little salt and pepper and sear
it all the way around.
After that, we transfer this
to the pressure cooker.
Got it.
So your mirepoix goes in.
We deglaze
with white wine.
Add some water.
And then, we're gonna
throw in our spices.
Got our pepper.
-Cumino.
Cumino.
Oregano, some garlic.
Salt.
So how long's this gonna take?
-35 minutes.
We're gonna take
the meat out.
Got it.
-We shred it.
So now, what we do:
add some olive oil.
Green bell peppers,
red bell peppers,
two tomatoes, onion.
Sauté that a little bit.
Do you need these now, Chef?
Not yet.
You make the taro root
chips yourself?
-Yes, we do.
-I'm just gonna eat the chips
as we go.
So what's next?
We got cumin, some garlic.
-Garlic, salt.
Salt, pepper.
Now our tomato sauce.
Now, we're gonna
make kinda
We're making this.
-our soup.
Now with the olives, the
bay leaf, the beef broth.
The stock
that we cooked it in.
-The stock we cooked in.
-Okay.
Shredded beef.
Now, how long is this gonna go?
-3 minutes.
And then,
we're gonna turn it off
and let it simmer.
So now, we're gonna
plate it, a bowl of rice.
We get our meat.
Pickled onion?
-Pickled onions,
parsley,
the taro chips.
And here we go.
These are beans
with butternut squash
and some smoked pork chop.
I like that there's
real texture to the meat.
Nice little touch
with the olives.
Peppers still have body.
Love that you put
the pickled onions on top.
Oh, that's great, man.
Let me take 18 more bites
and check this out.
Use a chip.
Oh.
That's a great idea.
I have the ropa vieja
for you.
The meat is really good.
The vegetables, along
with the Puerto Rican rice,
is just amazing.
I love this place.
It's a staple
of the Mission.
It's been here
for years.
GUY: Since 1974, in fact,
which is why this
husband-and-wife team
wanted to keep
the tradition going.
I used to come here
as a little kid.
The woman that was
working here wanted
to sell the restaurant,
so I said, "Okay.
I'll buy it and I'll
keep it the same."
When the new owners came in
and saved the place,
it was like -- pssh! --
it was amazing.
'Cause the locals gotta keep
their go-to spot for picadillo,
ceviche, and something
I've always loved to dig into.
Mofongo.
I love the mofongo.
It's a great dish.
The sauce is amazing.
I think that's what
tops it off perfectly.
Okay, Chef.
So we have achiote paste.
We add our bay leaf.
Oregano.
Salt and pepper, cumino.
Chile de árbol.
Nice and spicy.
Pineapple,
chili California.
Add some water.
Rub all the achiote
into the chilies.
Then, we're gonna make
slits to the pork
and stuff garlic
in there.
Kinda like Easter eggs.
-Wrap in foil.
-Pop it in the oven?
-Pop it in the oven.
-350. How long?
-3 hours.
All right. Let's do it.
Our plantain.
Got it.
-Fry them up about 3 minutes.
-All right.
We add garlic,
salt, and pepper,
chicharrón.
Mash 'em in the pelón.
-The pelón.
There you go. There we go.
-There we go. All right.
Now, we're gonna add
pork to this.
Look at that! Huh?
Little bit of the liquid.
Little bit of that fat.
One more time,
mix everything up.
Little more liquid here,
so it doesn't stick.
I've never seen mofongo
done this way.
Form it in the ramekin.
We're gonna make
an indention.
And now is when
we'll refry it.
Bring it out, let it cool.
We're gonna stuff it
with our pork.
Oh!
♪♪
The sauce is made
from the ropa vieja,
the vegetables.
Garnish it with some
pickled onions,
plantain,
a little parsley,
and there we go.
That's our mofongo.
-All right, brother.
[ Whimsical-suspenseful
tune plays ]
You know what?
That's really good mofongo.
Thank you very much.
Thank you
very much, Chef.
That seemed like
the longest period of time
in your life, huh?
-Oh, my God.
[ Laughter ]
Still get really good,
strong garlic flavor,
great texture.
And the pork?
Honestly, is spot-on.
This gravy that you make
with the ropa vieja sauce
and a little pickled onion
cleanse the palate really good.
All right.
A mofongo for you.
You gotta get this sauce
all over all this meat.
That crunch
with the soft inner.
It's the best mofongo
I've ever had.
Of all the places
in San Francisco,
this is the best place
to come to.
Handmade, scratchmade,
real deal.
Rafa, you did it, man.
-Thank you, brother.
-Very nice, fantastic. Ah!
-Thank you.
Up next...
in Key Largo, Florida --
Gorgeous.
Big-time family recipes --
Were you the food stylist
for the Fred Flintstone
cartoon?
Stepping straight
outta the boot.
That's about as oldschool
Italian American as it comes.
♪♪
So when I first
heard about Florida,
one of the terms
I heard was snowbird.
I said, "What's a snowbird?"
Well, it's everybody
that wants to avoid the snow.
They fly on down to Florida,
enjoy the great weather.
So how do you feed
all these East Coast folks
when they come down
to Key Largo?
If they want some real-deal,
oldschool Italian American
food, well,
you bring 'em right here,
to DiGiorgio's Cafe Largo.
♪♪
Seafood risotto.
They brought a little taste
of Italy to the Keys.
Chicken Marsala
in the window.
Hands down,
the best Italian food
you're gonna find anywhere.
GUY: Coming from
the DiGiorgio family cookbook
that Robert inherited from his
restaurateur father, Pasquale.
When did you come over
from Italy?
In 1962.
I was 21.
What year did you open
your first restaurant in Miami?
1968.
Robert followed
in his dad's footsteps
and opened this joint in 1992,
doing his own take
on the family classics.
Truffle lobster
mac & cheese.
Truffle lobster mac & cheese
is to die for.
The pasta is fresh.
It's made from scratch.
Well, we have a pasta
extruder here
that my father bought
and handed down to me.
-Beautiful machine.
We're gonna make a version
of cavatelli here.
You have two different
kinds of semolina.
One's grainier.
One's more powdery.
Put 'em in the hopper
of the pasta machine.
Salt-pepper-garlic powder
combination.
Then, we go in with the eggs.
We add water, until we get
the desired texture.
Look at this.
Can I just have one
of these in my house?
Ah!
Look at how gentle it is.
Throw me some soft music
behind this, please.
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ turning ♪
Like little tears of angels.
Gorgeous.
We're gonna take our whole
fresh Florida lobster.
We're gonna let it cook
for a few minutes.
And we're gonna add
our celery, carrots,
and onions.
-Little garlic.
Cracked black pepper.
Our brandy.
Brandy makes it dandy.
Gotta add my water.
Now, how long is
this gonna sit here?
About 2.5 hours.
Awesome.
Strain it.
Let's get
our frying pan hot.
Some of our
reduced stock.
Ready to add
our heavy cream.
Let that reduce a bit.
We're gonna add a little
roux to thicken it up.
Then, we have
a combination Asiago,
Fontina, Parmesan,
mozzarella,
little smoked Provolone
in there.
Living on the edge.
-Fold in our lobster.
There we go.
Our housemade
cavatelli.
There's a ton
of cheese in there.
And housemade truffle
breadcrumbs.
And then, we're gonna throw it
in the Salamander,
toast off the breadcrumbs.
-Pop 'em in.
And then, we're ready to serve.
-We're ready to go.
Look at that!
Mmm.
That lobster is outta bounds.
Real truffles are one
of my favorite things
in the entire world.
It can add little bit
of essence, that little --
That little kiss parlays
so well with cream sauce,
with lobster.
Pasta's nice.
It's got great chew to it.
The breadcrumb is so necessary.
Need a little bit of that
crunch coming through.
Nicely done.
Lobster truffle
mac & cheese.
It's succulent
and delicious.
Done exactly the way
it should be.
All right, some good friends
of mine here, Jim and Maria.
This is exactly
what I'm talking about:
East Coasters coming
down to Key Largo.
In Key Largo here,
there isn't Italian food
and this is the place.
Sausage and peppers pasta.
Veal chop Florentine.
All right.
What're we making next?
Our veal chop
cutlet Florentine.
I'm gonna die.
The veal chop Florentine
is like eating a dinosaur bone.
It's a huge piece
of veal, breaded,
smothered with mozzarella
cheese, mushrooms,
prosciutto ham.
How're we making this?
We're gonna trim it down
a little bit,
leave the bone on it.
pound it out
into a veal cutlet.
dust it in some flour.
'Kay.
Drown it
in some egg wash.
Make sure
you cover it all.
And then what's
this concoction here?
Panko breadcrumbs
with a lot
of shredded Parmesan
cheese in 'em.
Drench our sizzle platter
in olive oil.
You want olive oil
on both sides.
And this is just gonna
roast right in the oven?
That's it.
-What temp?
We do 425
about 20 minutes.
We're gonna top it with
prosciutto, mozzarella.
All right.
We are going to make
our Marsala wine
reduction.
Little olive oil.
We're gonna throw in
some butter.
Sliced mushrooms.
We're gonna add a pinch
of chopped garlic,
salt and pepper,
flour for our thickener.
And then, we're ready
for our Marsala wine.
Very nice.
And that's all she wrote.
Our wilted spinach.
Our porcini risotto.
Look at this chop, dude.
Were you the food stylist
for the Fred Flintstone cartoon?
[ chuckle ]
Marsala wine sauce.
That's about as oldschool
Italian American as it comes.
Just soaking up that sauce.
Tender, salty,
crunchy, garlicky.
I think you got
all the E's in there.
The mushrooms, the creminis,
and that Marsala,
just a touch of that sweetness.
-Mm-hmm.
I mean, it's dynamite. It's
exactly what you want it to be.
Veal chop Florentine.
It is fabulous.
The most incredible
thing about it is
the sauce
is just delicious.
You got a lot of great
restaurants in the area,
but to know all the history,
sharing your recipes
and your experience
with your son,
you're doing it right, buddy.
You're doing it right.
-Thank you, sir.
-Nice job.
So that's it for this trip!
But don't worry!
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week, on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
We're gonna do mofongo?
Gotta be ready for my mofongo.
Gotta get mofongo exercise on.
Stretch it out.
Here we go.
I am the mofongonator.
I don't know that you can say
that on television.