Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I'm out!
I am out.
...we've got funky joints
to grab a drink...
I know beer is not going to go
good with this at all.
...while digging into some
dynamite dishes...
This "Culinary
Flavortown" --
this is the amusement
park there.
...like a monster Minneapolis
brewery...
It might be our biggest
Triple D building yet.
...where the grub's as good
as the suds.
FIERI:
If this was a band,
it would be "Barky Bark
and The Funky Crunch."
And a restaurant bar
in Los Angeles...
You had me at hello.
...that's got me coming back
for more.
That's the pizza
I remember.
Plus a southern-style stop
in Miami...
That's one of the best
we've ever seen on the show.
...serving up comfort
gone crazy.
It's outstanding.
It's just out standing
in the rain by itself!
That's all right here
right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
So, I'm here in the Coral Gables
area of Florida,
just a couple blocks away
from Miracle Mile,
hanging out
with my buddy KC --
you know,
from The Sunshine Band?
Anyhow, KC, let me tell you
about this place.
This is the place where you're
going to get down tonight.
Really?
Yeah, and I'm going to tell you,
the food is so dynamite,
it's going to make you want
to shake your booty.
Come on, Guy.
I'm telling you, KC,
this guy makes a chicken
and dumpling,
and he does it from scratch,
and that's the way I like it.
That's the way
you like it.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay.
This is "The Local."
Steak tartare in the window.
The Local -- it really is just
a breath of fresh air.
There's always local beers
on tap,
and the cocktail list here
is pretty extensive.
Plate up shrimp and grits.
And the food itself --
I don't think "good"
accurately describes it.
I think it's marvelous.
FIERI: Thanks to the amped up,
down home grub
chef Phil Bryant been cooking up
since he rebooted the menu
in 2014.
What's the menu like?
Well, it's casual dining,
a lot of small plates.
And we focus mainly
on southern cooking
and regional ingredients.
I eat a lot of things here
that I never heard of
and I didn't know
that could be incorporated
inside a dish.
Lamb belly BLT.
The lamb belly BLT is fantastic.
MAN: I'm okay living
without bacon,
because lamb tastes
so much better.
Lamb belly?
Yeah, it's one
of those off cuts
that are getting
more and more popular.
Oh, then take me to Lamb Belly
Town, whatever that is.
We're going to make
our brine.
Start off
with some kosher salt.
Pig salt. Keep a little bit
of the color.
We got some
brown sugar here.
Some local
orange blossom honey.
Minced garlic.
A little pickling spice.
And then we're going
to add our water.
Bring this up to a boil.
And then we're going to pour
this over some ice.
And how long are we going to let
this brine that lamb belly?
For about 24 hours.
Okay.
So now we're going
to season it
with a little bit
of black pepper,
and then we're going to get it
on our stove top smoker.
Make it happen, baby.
Soak wood chips down.
What kind of wood?
Hickory.
Just going to perfume this
with a little smoke.
What, half hour
on this stove?
About 45 minutes.
Then finish it in the oven
at 225 for how long?
Two to three hours.
Let it cool,
then slice it by hand,
and that's put together
the BLT.
Exactly.
Now we're going to make pesto
out of some mustard greens.
Okay.
Olive oil.
Grated Parmesan.
Normally pestos are made
with pine nuts.
We're going to use peanut,
very much a southern ingredient.
Fresh lemon juice.
Crushed red pepper.
Minced garlic.
And kosher salt.
Blend that till it's nice
and smooth.
That works for me.
Sweetness from the nuts.
Now we're ready to grill
our lamb belly.
I'm impressed.
That looks great.
We got out bread
toasted off.
Local bakery?
Local bakery.
Going to smear a little bit
of our pesto on there,
add a lamb belly.
Is that how it always is?
Yeah, man.
Some heirloom tomatoes.
Put a little bit of olive oil
and sea salt.
And we got some more local
greens here.
Dress that lightly.
That's our lamb belly BLT.
Ridiculous.
You tell me that's not
a righteous looking BLT.
Without question,
you killed it.
Thanks, man.
It's dynamite.
You're getting all
the flavor of lamb
with that great, crunchy
texture of bacon.
Exactly.
Mmm.
Cooking it on the flat top
was definitely a great move.
Beautiful fresh greens
and heirloom tomato in there.
Perfect choice of the bread.
Mmm.
Dude, nicely done.
This Culinary Flavortown --
this is the amusement
park there.
Okay?
Go take a ride on the BLT.
We got the lamb belly BLT
right here.
Perfectly smokey.
It melts in your mouth.
And when he pairs it
with the pesto
that kind of just drenches
the bread -- it's phenomenal.
FIERI: And with a lineup loaded
with microbrews,
The Local really is a place
for locals to hang out,
like this cat.
So, you've lived down in Florida
for how long?
Born and raised here.
Welcome to my home.
There's really an energy of
the culinary world down here,
from great chefs
to funky little joints.
There's a great place
on every corner here.
FIERI: But there's something
about this one.
There's just not a lot of places
that you can get southern
comfort food.
FIERI: And not a lot of places
where you can get this.
Pick up roasted bone marrow.
Roasted bone marrow.
Yes.
Rich and decadent.
I wanted you to try
some bone marrow.
I heard you're a big fan.
-I'm a bone marrow junky.
We have our femur bone.
We brine this overnight,
a little bit of a housemade
barbecue spice,
a little bit of water,
some sugar.
Took it out of the brine,
and then coat it with more
of that barbecue spice
and roast it in the oven.
How long did you roast it?
Eight to ten minutes.
You have a nice, savory flavor.
Place that right on the bread
like so.
And then to add a little bit
more richness.
Yes, 'cause that's what
bone marrow needs.
Whipped horseradish butter.
And when all that stuff
melts together,
it'll be a nice
kind of sauce.
We're going to add
a little relish,
so this is egg whites,
capers,
a little bit
of anchovies, herbs,
and then some herbs, some
radishes, a little green onion.
I'd say bone marrow
gone wild right here.
And that's it.
Yo, you just can't fake
that kind of flavor.
I mean, that's just real deal,
genuine flavor going on there.
Mmm.
The little horseradish kiss
really makes a difference.
Fresh brightness
of the green onion
really takes it
to the next level.
Nicely done, my friend.
Thank you.
Here's your bone marrow.
Enjoy.
It's delicious.
In its uniqueness in it of
itself, it's worth ordering.
FIERI: When we come back,
something else worth an order.
WOMAN: Here's the hen
and buttermilk dumplings.
The hen and dumplings is one of
the best dishes that
they have out here.
Every time I get it,
my eyes just light up.
We'll see you in a bit.
Hey everybody, welcome to
The Local Craft Food & Drink
in Coral Gables.
Hey hey. Hey. Hey.
I'm...
You had stepped out, so...
I -- Oh.
...I just kind of...
Welcome back to The Local.
FIERI:
With this guy Chef Phil,
he's putting out some
serious southern comfort
right here in the middle
of a craft beer joint.
It warms itself with
that old southern flare.
I'm an old southern boy, so it's
as close as I get to home,
especially out here
in south Florida.
This is your hen and dumplings.
Enjoy.
-I love the hen and dumplings.
MAN: This thick, creamy gravy,
shredded hen,
dumplings, corn, chives,
I mean, it's one of the best
on the menu.
One of my favorite dishes,
I take on a chicken
and dumplings,
but we're going to make it
with stewing hens.
Why do you call them
stewing hens?
Well, stewing hens
are more mature birds.
They tend to have a more
chickeny kind of flavor.
A "chickeny."
If you're ever looking
for more "chickeny"
kind of chicken,
here you go.
We're going to braise these off
for a couple hours
and kind of make a broth
out of it.
A little bit of mirepoix,
parsley.
I'm going to add some water.
This is actually going to take
about four hours.
About four hours because of
the size of the, uh...
Stewing hen.
...stewing hen.
Okay, stalk's done.
Let the bird cool,
shred the meat.
Now we're going to make
the dumplings.
So, we're going to start
with some buttermilk.
Some butter. Garlic powder.
Onion powder.
Going to bring that
to a boil,
and then we're going to add
all-purpose flour.
So this is going to make
like a hot dough here.
Then we're going to transfer
that to a stand mixer.
We're going to add one egg
at a time
till it's all incorporated.
Roll it out,
cut it into shape.
And then we're going
to parboil it.
-So it stays in a form.
-Exactly.
Add a little bit
of whole butter.
We got our dumplings here.
The gigantic yokey-looking
things.
Get a little brown on that,
and then we're to add some
finely diced mirepoix.
Dig it.
Some of our
pulled hen meat.
Pulled hen meat.
This is some sour corn.
We salt and sugar it.
We let it sit out for 24 hours,
kind of start to ferment.
Interesting.
A little bit of caramelized
onion, salt, black pepper.
A little pinch
of crushed red pepper.
Some bourbon.
Burn out that alcohol.
Then we got our strained liquid
from cooking our hen.
Also known as chicken stock.
Chicken stock.
And we're going to add
Parmesan broth,
which is heavy cream that's been
simmered with Parmesan rinds.
A little bit more Parmesan.
Let all that come together.
Looks like a small portion,
but I bet you it's going
to be rich!
Just a little bit of some chive
oil and some fresh cut chive.
Hen and dumplings.
Ridiculous.
Oh, my gosh, dude.
It has the depth and the
richness of lobster bisque,
but chicken
and dumplified.
The dumpling's so nice and light
and delicate.
The broth is so rich.
Right amount of chicken.
Chive oil's on point.
A little red chili flake
is awesome.
That Parmesan cream sauce that
you make and the sour corn --
that's that acid kick that
you get inside of there.
Exactly.
That's a new definition
right there, buddy.
It's outstanding.
It's just out standing
in the rain by itself.
[ Laughs ]
Hen and dumplings
in the window!
He's able to mix all
these flavors together
and just create an explosion.
Those are dumpling pillows.
Oh, they are.
They're amazing.
Calamari pick up!
It's genuine. It's authentic.
It's from the heart.
Remarkable.
You're a real talent, man.
Thank you, man.
That's one of the best
we've ever seen on the show.
I can't say that
very often.
That's one of the best
I've ever seen.
Thank you, man.
Wow.
I'm going to go take a nap.
FIERI: Coming up, a Minneapolis
spot known for its brew...
I'll take some of that.
Yeah.
...also killing it in
the kitchen with their 'cue.
I compete barbecue.
I make a lot of barbecue.
That brisket stands up.
So, I'm right here on the border
of Saint Paul and Minneapolis,
Minnesota,
and I'm looking for this
scratch-made kitchen
that has this really
creative chef,
and it just happens
to be surrounded
by this ginormous brewery.
This is the Surly
Brewing Company.
This place is heaven.
When you think about Minnesota
beer, people just know Surly.
They were really leaders of
the whole craft beer movement.
FIERI: And like a lot
of craft breweries,
trailblazer Omar Ansari
had humble beginnings.
Yeah, when
the brewery started,
myself and Todd
our head brewer,
it was just the two of us
making beer,
selling beer,
delivering beer.
That was ten years ago.
Two years ago
we built this.
What was it
built out on this?
50,000 square feet.
Psh.
That might be our biggest
Triple D building yet.
FIERI: And their big reputation
goes way beyond the beer.
This stands on its own
as a restaurant.
Great beer hall food
taken to the next level.
FIERI: With Chef Jorge Guzman
putting out
those bold flavors mixed
with some big barbecue.
All right, we got
the pork shoulder
with the Brussels sprouts
and grits.
Get a huge potion of pulled pork
along with a little bit
different take
on a Brussels sprout.
What are we into?
Right now, we're making
our Thai chili vinaigrette
for our Brussels sprouts.
So, I start
with fresh lime juice.
Quite a bit of fish sauce.
Okay.
Some lime leaves.
Little bit of garlic.
Thai chilies.
Ginger.
Rice wine vinegar.
Copious amounts of sugar.
Hey, look mommy, milkshake!
Fresh lime zest.
Little chili sauce.
But we didn't throw it
just into the blender?
We want the seeds to be
in there.
We want a little bit
of texture.
I'll take some of that.
Yeah.
Now, we're going to make
our smoked pork shoulder.
Put a little bit
of black pepper,
salt, and cayenne pepper.
Rub this down.
Let it rest for an hour.
Then we go into the smoker.
225 for nine hours.
What kind wood are you
running here?
Hickory or cherry or apple.
Dig it.
All right,
we're gonna do grits,
so we put a ton of butter,
cheese, olive oil.
Grits in a beer hall.
Put a little
pickled jalapeños.
We make these
in house, too.
Going to do our
Brussels sprouts quick.
We just fry these for like two
or three minutes tops.
We hit it with out Thai chili
vinaigrette.
Toasted sesame seeds.
And then a touch of cilantro,
then we just mix those up.
You have to try that.
Oh.
Now we go with our pork,
and we'll pull off
some of that bark.
We just want a nice,
meaty chunk.
And that's it, man.
The grits are fantastic.
Look at the smoke ring
on that pork right there.
That smoke's no joke.
The dry rub goes incredibly
well with it.
It's great.
I'm impressed.
Pulled pork platter with sprouts
and a side of grits.
It's not too smokey,
but it's smokey enough
to know that it's barbecue.
Their Brussels sprouts
are super tasty.
Kind of crunchy on the outside
and nice and soft on the inside.
MAN: I love Surly Brewery
because it's just
a great addition
to the neighborhood.
FIERI: Which basically took
an act of Congress
to piece together.
Before 2011, it was illegal
to sell beer at a brewery
in Minnesota.
And then came what they now call
the Surly bill.
We got the idea in 2010.
We had to change the law.
It took you one year
to change the law?
It's beer.
I guess that's it.
MAN: Everybody comes for
the beer initially,
and then they realize,
"I'm also here for the food."
Hi, I have your top
brisket sandwich.
When you really are hungry for
a big sandwich that's flavorful,
it's a really good sandwich
to have.
Let's get into it.
Take our trim brisket.
So our same cayenne, salt
and black pepper rub?
Yes.
How long is that going
to stay on?
It's like an hour.
Got it.
What kind of wood
are you using?
For brisket we use
post oak or oak.
12 hours at 215.
Dynamite.
What are we going
to do now?
We're doing sweet
and smokey barbecue sauce.
We're using kosher salt.
Black pepper.
The garlic powder.
Onion powder.
Cayenne pepper. And then
a bourbon smoked paprika.
And then some brown sugar.
I gotcha.
Next we start
with some local honey.
Tomato sauce.
A little tomato paste.
Some ketchup. Liquid smoke.
Apple cider vinegar.
You don't do kids' birthdays,
do you?
We got a in-house clown,
actually.
Hey, I have
a traveling one.
Molasses.
Where did you learn to cook?
I've been cooking
for 20 years.
Single mom.
Started making dinner
for my brother and I.
You're a single mom?
I was. I'm married now,
so no more single mom.
I was pregnant last year.
[ Laughs ]
Browning seasoning.
Bourbon barrel-aged
Worcester sauce.
A little cola.
So, we'll mix this up
really nice,
and we'll add
our dry spice.
All right, so that's good.
There's our brisket.
Nothing wrong
with that one, sir.
If this was a band,
it would be "Barky Bark
and The Funky Crunch."
I don't know if I --
I'm out!
I am out.
Thank you, Minneapolis.
And then we'll add our sweet
and smokey barbecue.
Throw our brisket down.
Then we throw our slaw
right on top.
Oh, the diet plate.
I compete barbecue.
I make a lot of barbecue.
That brisket stands up.
Thanks, man.
Appreciate it.
You're using the flat.
You're bringing in the fat.
And the sauce, spot on.
Cool.
-Nice job, buddy.
-I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Oh, hey-oh.
Nice to meet you, too.
[ Both laugh ]
We got the brisket sandwich.
Really tender meat.
Really juicy.
Great smokey flavor.
The guy makes
real-deal food.
It's just a place where you can
come and get happy.
You're a really
dynamite chef.
I mean, to deliver quality
and quantity is no simple task.
It's like a Disney tour.
Is there a tram
that comes through?
Congratulations.
Nice job.
FIERI: Up next, it's New York
Italian in Hollywood...
Look at that.
...where you'll find pizza and
pasta with some meaty twists.
This dish is smoking, dude.
Fantastic.
♪♪
So, I'm here on Sunset Boulevard
in Hollywood,
and I tell you something,
I'm having a total blast
from the past.
You see, back in the day,
I was shooting
"Minute To Win It"
down here at
the Sunset Gower Studios.
When we had wrapped,
well, we'd come down
to check out this joint
for great pizza and beer.
You're going to love it.
This is Delancey Pizza and Bar.
Pizza up.
It is a little gem in the center
of historic Hollywood.
This takes me back to Italy
with a stopover in New York.
FIERI: Which was exactly what
NYC transplant George "AD"
had in mind when he opened
in 2008.
The whole idea was
New York City,
lower east side
Italian restaurant.
So he created the right recipes,
and now he has Chef David
Luevano dishing up his vision.
Calamari up.
-This food is legit.
-It is legit.
Legit's perfect.
-[ Laughs ]
Gramercy up!
The Gramercy is pizza nirvana.
Only place you can get multiple
forms of pork on a pizza
and it still feels light.
The guanciale on it really adds
something special.
The guanciale.
The pork cheeks.
This is just a great ratio
of fat to meat to flavor,
and we're going to cure it
and use it on the pizza.
On the pizza as a topping.
You had me at "hello."
Red chili flake.
Black pepper.
Some salt and sugar.
A little curing salt and...
...fresh thyme.
Rub this all over the meat,
and then throw the thyme up
on top of it.
Wrap it for a whole week.
And it's just going to start
pulling moisture out.
After it's been cured,
we wash all the salt off.
And then we're ready
to slice it thin and
throw it on the pizza?
Yeah.
Got it.
All right, make the dough
with just enough gluten
to stay together.
We're going to add
pizza sauce.
Whole milk mozzarella?
Yes.
We're going to add
the pepperoni.
Sopressata. Bacon.
I know beer is not going to go
good with this at all.
[ Laughs ]
Add the sausage.
A lot of people don't put raw
sausage on top of a pizza,
'cause you got to have
your timing right.
When it starts to cook
and it starts to render,
all that fat and flavor is going
to stay right on top of it.
That's why this pizza
is so rocking.
I remember having this when I
was shooting down the street.
And then the guanciale.
Guanciale.
We're good?
We're good.
At what temp we running
that oven at?
550.
Look at that.
See the guanciale just melts
right into it?
That's the pizza
I remember.
We do our garlic
infused saligao.
Slice it.
Nice looking pie.
That's a lot going on, man.
The guanciale, the sausage,
I mean, just all these
components start to cook down.
It creates so much flavor.
More flavor than normal.
Real deal, man.
Thank you, brother.
I appreciate it.
Get a glamorous pizza.
I mean, everything just works
perfectly together.
I love the crust.
Crust is what makes
a pizza anywhere.
Anda Lari and gnocchi,
pick it up.
MAN:
It's really tasty food,
but it's also just a place
you can just relax
and have a beer
and enjoy yourself.
MAN #2: The variety changes
all the time.
Yeah, you watch out, 'cause
this place gets packed.
The party's great.
I left here late.
-Yeah.
-A few times.
You don't necessarily think
of it as a restaurant,
more of a bar, it feels like.
-Right.
But then when you come in,
you get these dishes.
Gnocchi wild boar.
Wild boar gnocchi?
Yeah.
It's one of my favorite
dishes here.
So, let's get it going.
This wild boar leg.
Got it.
Some salt, pepper.
So we'll sear this off
on both sides.
Take it out,
add the mirepoix.
It's going to sweat
all those.
They're caramelized.
Then add red wine.
De-glaze it.
Chicken stock.
You can see a little bit
of that fat
floating to the top
of that chicken stock.
That's how I knew
he made it in house.
And a little water.
So it has enough liquid.
Drop these back in.
Bring them to a simmer.
Then we're going to go
into the oven at 350
for about three hours?
Yes.
'Cause it's tender and it
falls apart on itself.
Will you strain that sauce
and use that reduction
with the gnocchi?
Yeah.
Okay, Chef.
Right now we're going
to make our gnocchi.
So we've got
our rice potatoes.
Nice and light and tender.
Yes, sir.
We add eggs to it.
A little salt.
I just want it wet enough
so I can actually make a dough.
Now I'm going to add
two cups of flour.
We roll them out.
You cut them off
to about an inch.
This is about as loose
and as light
as you can possibly get it.
Little pillows,
I call them.
Get these boiling.
He's got a delicate hand.
And let those go for what?
Around four minutes
until they float up.
All right.
I'm going to brown them
on both sides.
While that's going,
you want me
to shred and eat
the wild boar, correct?
Uh, correct. [ Laughs ]
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
Just so I can make the sauce
and add the reduction.
Some fresh sage leaves,
olives.
Melt it with
a little butter.
Just got to reduce
the sauce.
Add the gnocchis.
And then we just
finish it off.
A little fried sage.
Mmm.
Brother, this gnocchi,
I'm surprised it can even
survive sitting on the fork,
'cause once
you put it in your mouth...
It melts.
...it's gone.
You get a little bit
of that texture
from when you
pan sautéed it,
which is nice, because sometimes
gnocchi can be just so mushy.
Now we're into the wild boar
au jus from the brazing liquid.
Mmm.
And the brininess
of the olive
really adds
that extra dimension.
This dish is smoking, dude.
Fantastic.
Gnocchi on the window!
These are little pillows
of perfection.
The wild boar gives it
a very strong flavor profile.
Bringing the clam.
MAN: The environment
they create here
has made this kind of
a second home.
I dig it, man, congratulations.
Nice place.
-Thank you.
-I'm glad I finally
made it back.
So, was this a great road trip
or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
We're going to slice
or pull the pork?
We're going to pull it.
You see all the karate moves
I just did there.
I taste a little bit if the --
We don't do this.
And then all of
a sudden [laughs]