I'm Guy Fieri, and we're rolling
out on a special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" in Maui.
Oh, boy! Hold on.
And we've got an island guru...
[ Laughs ]
...my brudda Reno,
riding shotgun.
You eat a lot
of moco loco?
Eat a lot of loco
loco moco moco.
First, true Hawaii classics...
I'm making sure
it's okay for you.
...that are more than
a full meal deal.
That's dynamite.
Plus, a Southern-style
pit-stop...
I should probably just start
eating these now.
...bringing big-time barbecue
right to the beach.
Oh, man!
Then...
[ Laughs ]
...the freshest
of the catch...
-That's legit.
-This is legit.
...turned into
a mouth-watering masterpiece.
Look at that.
Honestly, I don't know
if I can eat any more.
I might have to go
outside, lay down.
That's all right here,
right now,
when "Triple D"
rolls through Maui.
So, I'm here
for a special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives" in Maui.
Now, to make sure
that I keep everything legit,
I invited my buddy Chef Reno
from Fresh Catch over on Oahu.
Now, brother,
where are we?
We're on the Hana highway,
about two minutes
from Kahului Airport.
-Or the Maui airport.
-There you go.
Fantastic.
So, I know you fly into a town
and you want a "Triple D"
experience right now?
Don't worry.
You're in a good place.
This is Da Kitchen.
The Hawaiian Plate.
Home of the big food.
Poke bowl,
meat loaf in the window.
Da Kitchen really represents
the local food vibe.
It's really what we eat
here on the island.
Deuce musubi is up.
Pick it up.
Mariah and Les
are fantastic.
Mariah running the front
and Les in the back, cooking.
He's a mad scientist
back there.
Ow!
FIERI: But Les Tomita came into
this gig as a nightclub owner.
Ulti-moco in the window.
You see, after investing
in this joint in 2000,
his partner stiffed him.
But instead of bailing out,
he doubled down
and brought in his club
manager Mariah Brown.
-Deep fried Spam musubi.
-Thank you.
FIERI: Now together, they're
running the joint
and serving what they know best.
I grew up
eating this food.
Island soul food,
island comfort food.
I know what it's supposed
to taste like,
smell like, look like.
So he's nailing it
with this local classic.
The Notorious B.I.G.
FIERI: A.K.A. loco moco.
That's Hawaii's go-to
for big appetites.
What we're gonna do is fried
rice, patty, cheese,
SPAM, Portuguese sausage,
and bacon.
It's so good.
It's so big.
It's just insane.
Okay.
What are
we making first?
We're making chili
for our Notorious B.I.G.
It's a moco --
one of our mocos.
-It's a moco.
-Moco loco, yeah?
You eat
a lot of moco loco?
Eat a lot of loco
loco moco moco.
Mocomocomoco. All right,
let's get into this.
Just a little oil.
Put in the bacon.
Next SPAM.
The Portuguese sausage.
Onions. Bell peppers.
Okay, we're gonna move
this all to one side,
and now gonna bring
the burger in.
Is it 80/20
on your beef?
80/20 on the beef.
Now that we browned
our meats,
we're adding
our tomato sauce.
-Chili powder.
-Okay.
Now we're adding
the kidney beans.
A little salt and pepper.
How long is this
gonna cook down?
15 minutes.
Okay. What are
we making, boss?
Hamburger.
Liquid egg.
Sweet-bread bread crumbs.
Mayonnaise.
-Hawaiian butter?
Ground pork.
Chopped celery.
Pureed onions.
Salt. Pepper.
Pinch of celery salt.
And then we just
mix this burger in.
Patty this up.
We cook them to a medium.
And then when you're done
cooking it,
you put it
in the gravy?
Juices come out from
the burger into the gravy.
And it makes the gravy
more flavorful.
Way more flavorful.
All right, chef.
We're making
our fried rice.
A little bit
of bacon grease.
Brown the SPAM.
Put in
our Portuguese sausage.
Thought you would dance
or something.
[ Polynesian music plays ]
[ Laughter ]
Now we're adding our bacon.
This is our seasoned rice.
Then the green onions.
Let this cook for about two
or three more minutes.
-Put a little crisp on it.
-Yes.
Are we ready to see
Reno get after this plate?
They have two utensils
to eat with,
and I said this was the one
that was gonna be best.
So, I put
a little fried rice.
That ain't a little.
Then we're putting
in the burger.
So, you cook the burger
in the gravy the whole time.
-Yeah.
-You're gonna eat all of this.
Bring a little bit
of chili.
Little cheese.
Portuguese sausage.
Onion, mushrooms.
It's on.
Little gravy.
My mouth
is actually watering.
Green onions.
I'm just gonna take
a little bite first.
Take a bigger
bite than that.
No. I'm making sure
it's okay for you.
The burger coming out
of the gravy is dynamite.
Super juicy burger.
Great flavor.
Is this how most of
the moco locos are like?
This is the first
that I saw like this.
This is amazing.
I would name
this Moco Masterpiece
or Moco Madman or something.
I mean, this is...
Just keep on going.
No hurry. Enjoy.
Want a bigger spoon?
That's dynamite.
You want some now, don't you?
Can I get
an egg on top?
Get in there, cousin.
It's so good.
With that gravy,
with the crunch of the sausage.
Best one I ever eat yet.
-Thank you.
SERVER:
Notorious B.I.G. moco.
It just tastes awesome.
Unbelievable.
The homemade chili
is fantastic.
It binds everything together.
I've waited at least 45 minutes
in line to get in here.
There's a line to get in here?
Really?
They put water out
for everybody.
-Like what -- a trough?
-Pretty much.
Be able to
just go "Uhhh."
MAN:
Can't get enough of it.
The food just keeps
getting better and better.
All right, so,
here's the deal.
Reno's gonna sit here
and enjoy the rest
of this fantastic
moco loco monster madness.
We come back,
we'll make something else.
Something else we can
feed Chef Reno, huh?
Don't slow down.
We're hanging out in Da Kitchen
with da cousin and da uncle.
We'll see you in a bit.
That's the shot
right there.
Welcome back.
We're at Da Kitchen in Maui.
I'm hanging out
with my buddy Chef Reno.
You know him
from Fresh Catch,
and he told me how much
he loves moco loco,
so I figured why not make him
the biggest one that you could.
Come on, last bite.
Huh? Is that the best?
Huh, brudda? All right,
what are we making next?
Kalbi ribs.
The onolicious kalbi ribs.
Kalbi ribs
in the window.
The local meal that everybody
has to have
when you come to Hawaii.
MAN:
It's a marinated short rib
they use a homemade
teriyaki sauce for.
We got to do this
before he passes out
'cause I can't get
around the city without him.
We're making our
homemade teriyaki sauce.
Water -- warm water.
First up is the sugar.
Okay, so,
"kalabi" ribs?
-Kalbi ribs.
-"Kalabi." [ Laughs ]
I said it wrong?
-Kal...
-...bi.
There you go.
Now we're adding shoyu.
Next up --
Chopped garlic.
Chopped ginger.
Fresh O.J.
That's
your little citrus.
She's good to go.
-We get some ribs.
And we get some ribs
and start to marinate.
Thin-sliced.
We call that Korean sliced.
Right.
You had this at school lunch,
didn't you?
In Hawaii, everybody
eats kalbi, loco mocos.
We sell about 2,000 pounds
a week of these ribs.
-Seriously?
-Seriously, yeah.
So, the ribs are gonna marinate
in this for how long?
Yes.
24 to 36 hours.
Cook them on the charbroiler
for about five minutes.
[ Sizzling ]
What do you
serve it with?
Just white rice
and mac salad.
That's it. Just garnish --
little green onion.
Roasted sesame seed.
Look at them, dude.
They're huge.
Are we doing this
to Reno again?
-Yes, we are.
-Nice.
Can't beat those
sticky ribs.
That is tender.
Nice char on the meat.
This is the island one.
That teriyaki sauce
is magic.
Oh, that potato mac
is mean.
-Good. All right.
-It's potato and mac?
-Yes.
-The key --
you get the garlic
and you get the ginger.
It's there. Then you get
the note of the salt.
So it's not
overly sweet.
Look at that.
Is it the real deal?
This is the real deal.
I'll give this one a 10.
10!
All right.
I got to thank you.
All right, guys.
I got a kalbi ribs here.
They're juicy.
Every bite is just yummy.
Nice char.
You just can't stop eating it.
This is a must-stop, kind of
like a tourist attraction.
You really better
bring your appetite.
I mean, it's just something
you got to experience.
Funky joint.
Welcome to the island.
-Exactly. Good food.
-All right.
You can be my brother now.
Little work on your tan.
Brudda.
Nice job, chef.
Thank you.
Coming up on
our Maui adventure...
-Can I have another one?
-Unh-unh.
...a funky little
smoke shack...
This is competition
barbecue.
...puts some "howdy"
into "aloha."
You chose to treat this
like you got a little place
down in Memphis.
All right,
my brother Reno,
time for a little
mainland food, okay?
Now,
where are we exactly?
Well,
we're in Kihei, bro.
This is known for, like,
windsurfing, kite surfing,
snorkeling, shopping.
You know what they should be
known for from what I'm told?
Some out-of-bounds barbecue,
'cause this is Fat Daddy's.
Who's Your Daddy?
platter up!
By far the best barbecue
I've ever found on Maui.
SERVER:
Brisket for you there, my man.
Puts a perfect barbecue
smile on your face.
Pulled chicken sandwich up.
Love makes good barbecue,
and you can taste the love
in all his food.
FIERI: Which comes from owner
Chris Schobel's childhood.
I grew up smoking meats
in Pennsylvania.
I've just always loved it.
Loved it so much he bailed
on his Wall Street job,
went to culinary school,
landed in Hawaii,
and ended up reviving
a struggling
barbecue joint in 2013.
Schobel:
Hot barbecue in the window.
Great flavors,
rich bold.
Rib plate up!
Saint Louis-style rib.
Ah. It's too good.
So, let's talk about barbecue.
What kind do you make?
We're going a little bit
of North Carolina,
a little bit of Texas.
So, let's get
into the dry rub.
Chili powder. Kosher salt.
Some cumin. Paprika.
Some course ground pepper.
And then some nice brown sugar.
Now we're gonna rub
some ribs.
So, let me
ask you this.
Do you do the majority
of your smoking
in an old filing cabinet?
-No, no, no.
-No?
I have
a Southern Pride smoker.
I got
the Hawaiian Pride smoker.
You guys want to watch
a little clip?
-What was this?
-A cabinet.
It was a cabinet,
wasn't it?
Honestly, he does make
the best smoked octopus.
So, the smoker, what temp
are you running this at?
We smoke the ribs
at about 208.
Not 209.
Not 207.
And how long
are you gonna go?
We go about four and a half
to five hours.
-Wow. That's nice.
-All right.
I should probably
just start eating these now.
Nice bark. Pulling away
from the bone a little bit.
And don't take your silver
skin off, huh?
No. I like the crunch.
What are you doing?
Oh, that was fly.
So, we'll bring this in.
-Yep.
All right, let's do it.
Barbecue sauce.
Once again,
a little bit Texas-style.
I put the vinegar
and a little spice.
We like to use our beef fat
from the brisket.
Why do you use
the beef fat?
You know, it just adds
that layer of flavor.
Animal fat has got
10 times more flavor
than anything else.
Onions.
And then we use just
a straight base of ketchup.
-Got it.
-Little bit of molasses.
Yeah. That's a lot
a bit of molasses.
The "wash your sister"
sauce.
The "Wor-ces-ter-shire."
You know how
to say that?
"Wor-she-sher-sher-shire."
"Wor-shter-shire."
"Wor-shter-sheer."
I'm gonna put that
on the list.
All right. Salt.
-Is this our vinegar kick?
-That's our vinegar.
Apple cider vinegar.
Garlic powder.
Then for
a little bit of kick...
So a little hot sauce.
And then we add
the juice of one lemon.
We let it go about 35,
40 minutes.
Looking good.
So, let's cook up
a half rack, huh?
Give it a quick char.
-Right.
A little baste just for
a little more caramelization.
And you cut
the ribs for them.
Yeah.
We keep it simple.
Reno, you can see that
these are six of my ribs.
You can't put a plate
like this in front of a big guy
and not expect me
to eat it.
All right.
One rib.
Mmm. Delicious, huh?
-Amazing, bro.
Tender, really good smoke,
nice bark.
There's a big range
in barbecue, okay?
And you chose
to treat this
like you got a little place
down in Memphis.
That's a really good rib.
-Can I have another one?
-Unh-unh.
[ Laughter ]
All right. Go ahead.
And there's the rack
of ribs for you, bud.
They are fantastic.
MAN: Really smoky,
and they're tender,
but you still have
a little bit of bite left.
You know, it's nice
to have ribs done right.
And the pulled pork
for you, sir.
What is good barbecue
to you?
Has a nice texture,
falls apart,
caramelized on the outside,
tender, and full of flavor.
Full of flavor.
FIERI: And killer Q's got to
pair with some serious sides,
which is where Chris is
really getting bold on us.
Probably one of the best
corn breads you could ever taste
in the world.
-Oh, boy! Hold on.
Ah, the corn bread
is so, so good.
SCHOBEL:
Pretty good, right?
That's fantastic
corn bread.
Oh. Moist.
Comes from the big secret
ingredient -- creamed corn.
Now look at that, huh?
Ah, look at you
showing it to the camera!
Looks like we got
a professional on our hands.
From all the sides
to his smoked meat,
he just does
his food perfectly.
Fire up the burnt ends!
It's the fatty ends
of the brisket,
and then
he slow-cooks them --
nice, crisp bark on there.
Just delicious --
they melt in your mouth.
FIERI: And great burnt ends
start with great brisket.
Look at that.
Wow, bro.
SCHOBEL: That is
a 12-hour-smoked brisket.
You gonna serve this up how?
What are you gonna do with it?
We're gonna make this
into the burnt ends.
-All right, chef.
-All right.
We just like to take
the top, the cap, off.
See that?
-Ooh, look at that juice.
The cap
of the brisket --
That's this part --
a lot fattier.
We trim it up, cube it.
Should be just enough chew
to it, just enough smoke.
Oh!
That's the real deal
right there.
All right, so, now he's doing
a secondary cook on this.
You put it back for
another two, three hours?
Two, three hours, yep.
The ones I like to look for
have nice crust.
You see it almost looks like
a little piece of jerky.
All that color
right there?
That's all the smoke.
Burnt end sauce?
Yes, it is. Tangy.
-Dude, fantastic.
-That's good stuff.
It's like prime rib.
Like nuggets
of friendship.
Oh. That's amazing.
-It's competition barbecue.
-Oh, thanks, man.
Flavors are all balanced,
they're spot-on.
The sauce is dynamite.
Ah, man!
Burnt ends up!
Can't get any better
burnt ends on Maui.
The smoke is just driving
through the dish.
Get a double order so I can
have it for lunch tomorrow.
Amen to that.
Throwing up on it, Roscoe.
Love the barbecue here.
Really puts the "wowee"
back in Maui.
Excellent job.
Probably the best barbecue
I ever eat in Hawaii, bro.
Thank you very much.
Means a lot.
-Amazing.
The godfather of one island
of "Triple D"-ness
passing the torch.
-Nice.
Up next, we're hooking up
with Reno's partner in crime...
How did my show just turn into
an infomercial buddy love fest?
...for some
out-of-bounds poke...
You taught me well,
Rennie.
...served up
in some crazy ways.
People normally do this?
-Oh, not like this.
So, here we are
on the final stop
of this awesome
"Triple D" Maui tour.
Chef Reno, you're
calling the ball.
What do you got?
Well, you know
how much I love my poke, bro.
Yes, I know.
You got four restaurants.
He makes poke
everywhere he goes.
This is my protégé, bro.
He's the real deal.
The real deal.
This is the real deal
right here, man.
This is Like Poke...?
WOMAN: Ahi katsu.
It's the best
food truck on the island.
I got a shoyu
ginger coming up.
You cannot get fresher
fish anywhere
unless you get it out
of the ocean yourself.
FIERI: That's 'cause
for Chef Danny Kalahiki,
life is definitely a beach.
Aloha! Welcome.
What can we get for you today?
As a local boy
and ex-pro surfer,
this dude knows a thing
or two about seafood.
...I got two shoyu
ginger pokes ready.
Then after culinary school
and working in local joints,
he opened up
his own truck in 2009
and made it all about
his lifestyle.
Everything in here
is fresh every day.
I keep it super simple,
because I'm lazy
and I want to go surfing.
Okay. And where did you
learn to cut fish?
It wasn't until
I went over to Ren's
that I really learned
how to cut fish.
To who?
Rennie --
Big Rennie over here.
You see Reno coming, everybody's
"Oh, Big Rennie!"
[ Laughs ]
Like Poke...? has the best poke
on the island, hands down.
Hey, your fried poke.
Here you go.
Very similar to sushi,
like sashimi.
I think the best way to get
is when it's raw
and fresh like this.
All right,
let's do the fish.
Quarter yellowfin fresh tuna.
Caught yesterday.
This is the primo stuff.
This is what we cut
the poke out of.
Once you put poke cubes
into a bowl
and you add
all the sauces,
sometimes
you lose the fish.
In order to ensure
you still taste the fish,
I cut it big.
Jumbo. That's how to cut
some poke, Big Dan.
I use watercress
instead of green onions,
opposed
to most poke places.
Red onion.
-Little crunch, little sweet.
And this is a little
poke seasoning
learned
from Chef Ren here.
Hold on.
Let's say "Chef Reno."
-Chef Reno.
Japanese chili
pepper powder,
toasted sesame seeds.
Ginger oil.
-Okay.
It gives it a nice shine.
I learned that
from Chef Reno.
See? Getting better.
And then
we have our poke sauce.
A little bit of soy,
some sugar,
and some oyster sauce
in there.
This is as fresh
as it comes.
You take about 1/2 pound
of poke.
It's so tender that
before I even bit into it,
it started to melt.
-I taught you well, bro.
-You taught me well, Rennie.
You will never
find it that fresh.
That's legit.
-This is legit.
You can still taste the fish
even underneath the sauces.
They complement
each other really well.
I think it's terrific.
Some of my fellow UNLV,
Las Vegas friends,
the Ross family,
on vacation,
eating fantastic poke.
What do you think?
-It's great.
-It is tasty, huh?
-First time I've ever had it.
-First time!
It's very flavorful
in each bite.
Honestly, I don't know
if I can eat any more.
I might have to go
outside, lay down.
Well, this next one
is definitely the heavy hitter.
This is the poke bake.
Baked poke is delicious.
Poke bake.
Comes out nice and warm,
but still raw.
MAN: They put a little
furikake seasoning.
It's like a seaweed,
sesame seed, smoky flavor.
Phenomenal.
Okay, let's do it
before I pass out.
We're gonna take
our fresh poke again.
That I'm enjoying raw
just by itself.
We're gonna top it
with our everything sauce.
It's mayonnaise
and shoyu and sugar.
Gonna pop it in the oven
for a couple minutes
so the top just gets
all caramelized.
Caramelized on top,
but just warm through.
And then we take
island furikake
that we all love
so much here in the islands.
And then we take a little bit
of our homemade salad dressing.
If you got to operate
heavy machinery after this,
don't eat this one.
-Really?
Yeah.
Oh.
Do people normally do this?
-Oh, not like this.
-That's legit, dude.
That right there
is creamy.
It actually takes a lot
of the flavor of the fish
and the shoyu sauce,
onions,
and kind of wakes it up,
so it's super flavorful.
SERVER: Poke bake.
Just that fresh
fish flavor melts in your mouth.
It's amazing.
There's some of the best
food at the roadside.
Maui's flooded
with high-end dining.
There's hardly any
local affordable dining.
So my passion
is feeding the locals.
Here's your fried poke,
sweetie.
Have a good day. Aloha.
If you think
regular poke is good,
you should have it fried
how Danny makes it.
It come out unreal.
My kid asks for this
every single day.
So, next we're gonna just take
that same poke we just mixed,
and we're gonna make
our fried poke.
Now, this to me
is a little sacrilege.
Look at that.
I mean, that is about
as beautiful as it comes,
and we're gonna
deep fry it.
We're gonna take
some of our fresh poke
right into
our seasoned flour.
What's in the dust?
It's got
a little bit of everything.
It's...flour.
-It's a fry flour.
-Yeah.
And then we're just gonna
right into the fryer.
It's gonna be fast --
30 seconds.
It gets evenly cooked
all the way around.
Just in this
nice cardboard box?
And we just put it
right on the plate.
We top it off here
with our crack sauce --
also kind of
developed by Reno.
It's a spinoff.
That looks like straight
my sauce, not a spinoff.
Pretty close.
It's still raw
in the center.
That's how fast
you cooked it.
Just enough crispiness.
It's a thin, thin,
thin amount of batter,
good flavor.
Like I said, I learned
from the master.
How did my show
just turn into
an infomercial
buddy love fest?
[ Laughs ]
The spices are great.
The sauce
is absolutely amazing.
I'm liking the marinade.
Little bit different flavor
than what I'm used to.
There's a sweetness
to it, but really nice.
Ever time I'm craving poke,
I come here.
You embody being a chef
and being a restaurant owner,
you love people,
you love to treat
your ingredients with respect,
you treat it like it's a
500-seat fine-dining restaurant.
You've got a lot
to be proud of.
Did a good job.
I'm impressed.
Nice job, my brother.
I know what you're doing
right now. You're thinking,
"How do I get
all these recipes?"
Here's what you do.
You go to foodnetwork.com/DDD,
find out all these
fantastic places,
so the next time
you come to Maui,
you don't have
to call my brother Reno
to drive you around.
See you next week.
Peace out.
Aloha, guys.
Now, to make sure that I keep
everything Hawaiian legit,
I invite one of my favorite
Hawaiian chefs,
Chef Reno fr--
Chef, chef.
Hawaiian, Hawaiian.
Cheffity, chef, chef, chef.