I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoo!
...we're hitting up
small towns...
Oh, this is cool.
...serving up
some big flavors.
Look at me.
I can't stop eating it.
...like in a Vincentown,
New Jersey, diner...
Make the magic happen,
baby.
...stacking it up
for generations.
I mean, that's doing it
old-school the right way.
...and a 1700's joint
in Rocky Hill, New Jersey...
I love the way
you're rolling this.
...dishing out pub grub
with a side of history...
Think I can believe
George Washington came here
if he had this burger.
...and
in Raymond, New Hampshire...
I've never seen
anything like this.
...a butcher shop
going 100% next level.
This might be making a brick
at the capitol of Flavortown.
[ Marcotte chuckles ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in New Hampshire
in a little town known
as "Raymond,"
where they only got
about 10,000 people,
and it's located right between
Manchester and Portsmouth.
Now, what am I doing
all the way out here, you ask?
Well,
I'm here to check out a joint
that's scratch-making just about
everything under the sun.
This is The Tuckaway Tavern
and Butchery.
James, how far out
on that fried chicken?
JAMES:
Three minutes, Chef.
When you come to Tuckaway,
you better come here hungry.
Butcher's Block, table 6.
You need about 20 minutes to
figure out what you want to eat.
That's because there's
a massive amount to choose from,
ever since Chef Bobby Marcotte
and Paul Simbliaris
transformed a simple
New Hampshire meat market
into a 14,000-square-foot
butcher shop
and dining destination.
I've never seen
anything like this.
-Did you build the building?
-The building was here.
We came in
and completely renovated it.
Wow.
Now, who developed
all the recipes?
That would be me.
What Bobby puts out on a daily
basis is just incredible.
His imagination
is endless with food.
Chili cheese corn hole up.
The chili cheese corn dogs
are super popular here.
Everyone loves them.
It's a house-made hot dog,
and then they dip it into batter
and deep-fry it.
All right, what are
we gonna make first?
We're gonna make
our meat mixture
for our chili cheese
corn holes.
So I got
some Angus chuck roll...
Okay.
...and some boneless
pork butt.
-About 1/3, 2/3.
-Yep.
So in the grinder --
there we go.
With just one grind?
Twice, actually.
Now we go into the spice?
Correct.
Ground cumin.
Okay.
Salt, some black pepper,
granulated garlic and onion,
pink curing salt,
brown sugar,
ground jalapeño,
coriander, mace,
ancho chili powder,
sugar,
celery seed,
smoked paprika.
This monster amount
of spice
goes in that
little bit of meat?
We got to Flavortown.
This might be making a brick
at the capitol of Flavortown.
[ Chuckles ]
So mix this up,
let it cure for two days...
Exactly.
...then we take it
to the buffalo chopper?
Correct.
[ Machinery grinding loudly ]
These things are wicked.
We're bringing all that
fat and meat together.
That's what gives you
the texture of the hot dog.
Emulsify it with some ice.
Keep it from heating up,
so it doesn't get gummy.
Little bit of milk powder --
helps keep everything together.
Cheddar.
So a little cheddar.
-Some jalapeño.
-And finish it with American.
[ Grinding stops ]
Ohh.
[ Laughs ]
I should have told everybody
at home to mute your channel,
and we would've just thrown
some subtitles at the bottom.
That is loud!
So now,
roll it in a ball.
We're gonna steam them
for 10, 12 minutes.
Now we're gonna make
the batter.
Okay. Start us off.
Eggs, some milk, cornmeal,
flour, baking powder,
baking soda,
salt, sugar...
Sugar.
...and a little butter.
And then we'll dredge
the corn holes, dip them in.
Fry them off at 350?
Exactly.
All right.
So now we're gonna plate.
We're really gonna stuff them
in that bag?
Just three.
So do I dip the whole bag
in there, too?
[ Laughs ]
Look at that.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
Got the jalapeño in there,
got a couple different
cheese in there.
Lord knows you ripped off
the entire spice cabinet.
You didn't emulsify
the fat so much
that you still have
good texture of the meat.
I want them to know
it's hand-crafted.
You know what I mean?
You're selling it
right off the bat, brother.
Awesome.
That's dynamite.
Okay, so what
do I have here?
We got sriracha ketchup
for a little more heat,
in case
it's not hot enough.
Okay.
That pairs perfectly.
And then
our house-made chili queso.
Mmm. I don't eat
a lot of corn dogs,
but when I do, that would be
the one I'd want to have.
Thank you, Chef.
Fantastic.
Chef Bobby, gangster.
WOMAN: You can tell that
it's just really fresh.
When you bite in, the cheese
just melts right out.
It reminds me a little bit of
childhood -- it's so whimsical.
You can't get enough
of the food.
It's not just the restaurant.
They have
the whole butcher shop
with that giant case
that you can find
anything you need.
FIERI: Including 20 flavors
of house-made sausage,
like maple blueberry
and apple bacon,
plus salads, homemade jams,
and hot sauces.
I have seen some joints
in my day, man.
This is ridiculous.
There's even over
40 types of marinated meat.
So you can grab
grill-ready versions
of this New England original.
WOMAN: Steak tips.
Gonna have you try
some house tips,
teriyaki tips,
and our maple bourbon tips.
Give me the process
on these.
These are vacuum-tumbled
with each individual marinade,
and then we let them sit,
minimum, 48 hours.
Mmm. The tenderness
of skirt steak,
the meatiness
of flank steak,
but super tender,
almost getting filet tender.
The great thing is people
can take this home
and be the hero at home.
Absolutely.
Nice job.
Thank you.
MAN: House steak tips.
It's all just...
premium quality.
That's why we come
so often.
All right, what do you got
for me next?
Well, hang on. Don't tell us.
Don't tell us.
So, when we come back,
we're gonna see --
see your encore.
-Gonna be good, right?
-Hope so.
Don't "hope so."
Of course it is!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So here we are.
We're hanging out
in Raymond, New Hampshire,
with Chef Bobby
at The Tuckaway Tavern
and Butchery.
And when I tell you
that he's just one man,
I don't know if it's true,
because he is making more food
and doing more production --
Dude, I've never seen
anything like it.
What's the dish
we're gonna make next?
We're going to make
the Whole Tuckin' Farm Burger.
And what is in
the Tuckin' Farm Burger?
A burger, fried chicken,
bacon, cheese,
topped with Tuck Sauce.
Tuckin' sandwich up.
It's a monster --
look at this.
An intense amount of flavor.
Let's go.
So this is
our house seasoning.
Okay.
I want to know
what that is.
That's...
[ Chuckling ] Yeah.
Yeah, a lot of people do.
Why didn't you tell me
what --
that was gonna be
that strong?
[ Whistles ]
There's an acid
of some sort in there.
For sure.
Whoo!
So we got some paprika,
some granulated garlic
and onion,
orange juice powder.
Where did you start learning
about all the powders?
I do my diligence.
"I do my thing."
Black pepper, minced onion,
minced garlic,
some mustard seed,
sugar,
coarse black pepper...
Of course.
...ground mustard,
and our house spice.
We actually season the patty
and let that sit overnight.
Okay, straight chuck?
Chuck Angus.
Sounds like a band.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay, what are we into,
boss?
So now we're gonna marinate
our chicken
in the vacuum tumbler.
Start with some oil.
Vinegar.
And a bunch
of the house spice.
So how long is
this gonna tumble?
25 minutes.
So we've got out chicken
that's been marinated,
and then it'll just sit
in the walk-in
till it's ready to go
for service?
Minimum, 24 hours.
Okay.
All right, so we're gonna
pound this out nice and thin.
Okay.
We're gonna dredge that.
Little flour
and cornflakes,
egg wash,
and then we go again.
Down in the fryer, 350?
Absolutely.
Burger goes on?
Yep.
So we got out burger,
fried chicken,
applewood bacon, cheddar.
Wow!
Last but not least,
the Tuck sauce.
Well, what is in
the Tuck sauce?
Mayonnaise,
Worcestershire sauce,
hot sauce,
our house seasoning.
That's all she wrote.
Oh, and then you got
a little brand on top,
'cause you don't
have enough to do.
Get the whole barnyard
here.
Fried chicken's
the real deal.
It's great.
It's got a great flavor,
really nice and tender.
Ground chuck's no slouch.
And as a package deal,
that's a heck of a meal.
It's just all
the little pieces.
It's melting the cheese
onto the chicken.
After it comes
out of the fryer,
the bacon's nice
and crispy.
The Tuckaway sauce --
I mean, absolutely --
all plays together.
I wanted it to be great,
and it is.
Thank you.
Well done, Chef.
It's so big, it will last you
a day or two, at least.
Explodes with flavor.
MAN: Driving over an hour
to get here one way --
still doesn't us from coming
at least once a week.
Always have a good time
at Tuckaway Tavern.
-Nice job. Beautiful place.
-Thank you.
It's a carnivore emporium.
I like that.
You might want to take that
and work some of that in there.
#CarnivoreEmporium.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up...
a real-deal diner
in Vincentown, New Jersey...
I love it.
...piling on the comfort...
Don't be shy with that.
...and going berserk
with the breakfast.
It's like
a wedding cake.
We cure it.
That's right.
It's what we do.
We hot dog it.
We hot dog it...dummy.
[ Laughter ]
[ Beeps ]
So, I'm here
in the Southampton Township
of New Jersey
to check out a classic
stainless-steel diner from 1953.
But, uh...
[ Record scratches ]
...unfortunately,
it's not here anymore,
you see, because
the Melissaratos brothers
brought it in '69,
and they realized,
well, it just wasn't big enough.
So in '73, they sold it,
and they built this monster.
This is the Vincentown Diner.
Edgar:
One hot cake working, please.
MAN: Every time you come in,
you know you're gonna get
a really good meal.
Country omelet.
Everything comes from scratch.
I need a prime rib, TC.
Doesn't really even compare
to other diners.
FIERI: 'Cause after
owner Demetrios Melissaratos
took over
the family diner business,
he broke from tradition.
We have upgraded the menu
dramatically.
We're in the middle
of farm country right here.
We buy all the local
vegetables and fruits.
And executive chef
Jason Edgar
is using local grass-fed beef
for this tower of power.
Mile High Meatloaf.
FIERI: Why is it Mile High?
It's about this high
off the plate.
-No, it's not.
-It's pretty big.
-Seriously?
-It's big.
It's like
a reverse meatloaf sandwich.
And the pieces
are thick and meaty.
We're gonna make
the meatloaf?
Yep. We got
our ground beef, 75/25.
Going big.
Ground Italian sausage.
Green and red peppers,
white onions
that I've cooked down
for a long time.
Yeah, when people put
raw veggies in meatloaf,
it drives me crazy.
No, no, no.
Now, I got
some panko bread crumb
that I've crushed
some roasted garlic into.
And then milk.
So you got your panade.
Yes.
Beaten organic eggs.
Some of the meatloaf sauce.
What do we got?
Well, we got some ketchup,
maple syrup, steak sauce,
hot sauce,
mozzarella steak seasoning.
Doctor.
Just some salt and pepper.
So we'll take this
into the pan?
Pack it in.
So, in the oven --
what temp?
350, about an hour,
hour and a half.
Then we bring it out,
and we brush some more of that
meatloaf sauce on the top.
Got it. Let it glaze.
Put it back in to glaze.
Got it.
Yeah, then we let it cool.
We unmold. We slice it.
It gets seared
on the flat top.
You make the gravy
yourself?
We make the gravy.
Got to make some gravy.
All right,
let's make some gravy.
All right.
I've roasted
some veal bones.
I'm gonna put them
in the pot
with some roasted vegetables
and rosemary, thyme.
Fill it up with water.
How long we gonna let that
cook down for?
6, 7 hours until
all that collagen breaks down.
Strain it.
Yes, sir.
And that's the foundation
of all the gravy?
Yes.
I love it.
I mean, that's doing it
old-school the right way.
Some butter.
Small amount of butter.
Little bit.
Build the roux.
I'm gonna add some more
of the roasted mirepoix.
Put some flour in there.
We cook the flour
for a couple of minutes,
then we go in
with our stock.
Little demiglace.
Homemade tomato sauce.
Do one spoon of beef base,
just to amp it up
a little bit.
Now we got some
ground prime rib
and some flat-leaf parsley.
Okay, so you let that
sit there and cook down,
and then later take
the immersion blender to it?
Yes, sir.
And this will go...
Right on
the Mile High Meatloaf.
Got it.
All right, Chef.
Make the magic happen, baby.
We got our meatloaf
seared off.
We're gonna go down
with a nice scoop
of our roasted garlic mash.
One piece of meatloaf,
another scoop of mash.
I get the Mile High thing
now, Chef.
We're gonna go on
with our gravy.
Don't be shy with that.
A little frizzle.
Some of our veg mix.
Start at the knee.
[ Laughs ]
The thing that
impressed me the most
has been the prime rib
into the gravy.
Oh, thank you.
Wow.
Mashed potatoes
are spot-on.
The meatloaf is tender.
You definitely get some
of that Italian sausage.
Love the little caramelization
you put on it
when you finish it
on the flat top.
This is tender.
This is juicy.
Oh! Look at me.
I can't stop eating it.
Well done, brother.
Thank you, man.
That's good stuff.
Pick up, Mile High Meatloaf.
When you take a bite,
you get the best of everything.
Just the way you want it --
just perfect.
I love Vincentown because
of the family atmosphere.
FIERI:
Something that's been important
since Demetrios started
working here as a kid,
when his dad and uncles
owned the place.
Did your dad know
that you bought it,
or had your dad passed?
He passed.
He's the guy
in the blue suit?
Yep.
Oh, he's happy, man.
He's got to be proud
that his kid's taken over...
...and that
he's back in the booths,
serving up creative twists
on diner classics.
Pick up,
two apple pie French toasts.
Breakfast or dinner,
that's the dish for me.
Melt-in-your-mouth
delicious.
All right, Chef.
Next up?
We're gonna make
our apple mix
for the apple pie
French toast.
Start with some apple juice
and brown sugar,
cinnamon sticks.
A little "thinnamon."
What type of apple?
Fuji.
We're gonna let this cook down
about 10, 15 minutes,
until the apples
are nice and soft.
Okay, up next, Chef...
We got the salted caramel
for the apple pie French toast.
Get it.
A little bit of water,
some sugar.
This is gonna go
until the sugar caramelizes.
Got it.
Then we're gonna go in
with butter, heavy cream.
And then to make it
salted caramel...
We add some salt.
That's it.
Oh, see, that's
the right amount of salt.
-Yeah.
-Mmm. That's dynamite.
I don't like sweets,
but I like salted caramel.
And the French toast --
how we making that?
Make our
French toast batter.
Get a thick-sliced white bread
we get from a local bakery.
Got it.
Cook it on our flat top.
We did it.
One layer of French toast.
Pile on
those cooked-down apples.
Another French toast.
Another pile of apples.
One more French toast.
Some apples for good luck.
Those apples
really do cook down.
Salted caramel.
Is this dessert
or breakfast?
Uh, whichever you prefer.
Gonna hit it with
a little pinch of the crumble.
We'll finish
with some whipped cream.
There you go --
apple pie French toast.
All right, so I got
to call my son Ryder.
Ryder is
a French toast aficionado.
Here he is.
Ryder, I want you to take a look
at this French toast --
cinnamon and apples
with caramel sauce
and whipped cream.
Okay, wow.
I'm gonna give you
a bite of it right now. Ready?
How'd it taste?
[ Laughs ]
Yeah.
It's like a wedding cake.
Nice toast.
You still got
some chew to it.
The apples are cooked
just enough.
The little crumble on top
is a nice little touch.
-But the caramel sauce, bro?
-Yeah.
I mean, you should just have,
like, a caramel bath out there.
People could just
drag bacon through it.
Watch out for this guy.
The apple pie French toast.
This plate defines
comfort food for me.
WOMAN: It tastes exactly
like an apple pie
that my grandmother made.
WOMAN #2: No matter where
you're coming from,
the Vincentown Diner
should be on your list.
Congrats, man.
Your dad would be very proud.
Thank you.
Up next, a funky old spot
in Rocky Hill, New Jersey...
[ English accent ]
Gotcha, guv'nor.
...reinventing a burger...
There you go.
...and getting groovy
with a bar food favorite.
You're gonna eat
disco fries,
you better eat
damn good disco fries,
and that's
what you're making.
♪♪
[ Beeps ]
So I'm here
in the borough of Rocky Hill,
which is about 4 miles
from Princeton, New Jersey,
to check out a joint
that's in a building from 1747.
Now, there's a lot of history
and rumors about this place,
like George Washington
used to hang out here.
Well, that might be true
if he saw this chef's menu.
This is Rocky Hill Inn.
[ Sizzling ]
Belly and Clams, table 20.
We get cravings
for the Rocky Hill Inn.
I walked in the door.
I was like, "I'm home."
The kitchen's always on point.
FIERI: And by kitchen,
he means real-deal chef
and owner Evan Blomgren.
Would you just yell,
"Captain Caveman"
for me one time?
Captain Caveman!
[ Laughs ]
And when he picked up
this mid-1700s joint
a few years back,
well, it came loaded
with history.
George Washington's
been here.
Yes, and it was
somebody's house.
And then someone turned it
into a restaurant.
Yes.
Well, I came in here
trying to do higher-end food,
but the town was like,
"What is he trying to do?"
So I started doing burgers.
RHI burger.
WOMAN: It's a gastropub.
There's no other food
in the area like this at all.
FIERI: That's 'cause he's using
his classical culinary training
to take
pub food full tilt.
Pork belly disco fries.
MAN: Disco fries are a really
common thing in New Jersey.
Everyone has their own version.
Explain to everybody at home
what disco fries are.
It's a fry with putting,
like, cheese and meat.
That kind of late-night food
everybody wanted to eat
after they left
the discos.
Your disco fries
have pork belly?
And a malt vinaigrette.
Malt vinaigrette?
After an English pub.
You're gonna have to speak
in English accent from now on.
Gotcha.
[ English accent ]
Gotcha, guv'nor.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna add some shallots.
Shallots!
Dijon mustard.
Malt vinegar.
Malt vinegar!
[ Laughs ]
Chopped herbs.
Herbs.
[ Normal voice ] It's rosemary,
thyme, and oregano?
Yep. We'll put
a little salt in there,
a little cracked pepper.
Now we're gonna season
our pork belly.
This is not
locally sourced.
We're still gonna be okay.
We're still gonna be friends.
I try.
We're still gonna watch
Saturday cartoons.
[ Laughs ]
[ Grunting ]
Season it
with some salt and pepper.
Hot pan, little oil.
There we go.
Sear this off
on both sides?
Mm-hmm.
Now mirepoix,
your house herb mix.
We want to get
the aromatics going, you know?
I feel the magic.
Yeah.
We deglaze
with the white wine.
Now the pork belly
goes back in.
On top of that goes the...
Pork stock.
Into the oven -- how long?
2 1/2 hours.
Bring it out. Let it cool.
Cube it.
We're gonna cook
those on the flat top?
Mm-hmm,
and then we're gonna make
our pork belly fries.
Yeah!
We got our fries
that we handcut here.
Double fried.
We season with our house blend
and salt and pepper.
Herbs.
I love the way
you're rolling this.
Mmm!
Put some banana peppers
on there.
Fontina cheese.
Throw under the boiler.
Melt it up nice.
Put our malt vinaigrette
that we made earlier.
And we finish
with scallions.
Mmm.
Unctuous pork.
Freshness coming from the
peppers and the green onion.
I like the little fresh herb mix
that you throw in there.
And that vinaigrette --
that turbocharges the dish.
This is a way more refined
disco fries dish
than I think anybody's
probably gonna ever have.
Oh. If you're gonna eat
disco fries,
you better eat
damn good disco fries,
and that's
what you're making.
Thank you.
Well done. Whoa!
The disco fries are awesome.
There was just
so many textures going on.
I have sitting at the table
two of my Food Network brass,
Andrew and Madeline.
I want you to give me
your best description
of these disco fries.
First, there's
the cheese factor.
Andrew or me?
[ Laughter ]
Ba-dum-pum!
We'll be here all week.
Crisp fries.
Crisp pork belly.
MAN: The substitution
for the vinaigrette
instead of the gravy --
that just made it.
Pulled pork mac
in the window.
His menu is unique.
It's always something different.
FIERI: [ Chuckling ]
Even when it comes to burgers.
I'm enjoying
the fried green tomato burger.
The bacon jam,
the goat cheese --
it's just...spectacular.
What are we making next?
We're gonna make
the bacon jam.
Diced-up
applewood-smoked bacon.
Let this render down.
Red and white onion, diced.
And then some chopped garlic.
Dried mustard.
Very nice.
Chili powder.
And the ground ginger.
Quite an interesting profile
we have going here.
Yeah, right?
Next up?
Bourbon.
Just want to let that burn off
a little bit.
[ Clock ticking ]
Okay.
How about them Bears?
[ Laughter ]
Sherry vinegar.
Maple syrup.
Brown sugar.
And a little bit of herbs.
Salt.
Cook down
a little bit more?
Let it cook down
until it's jammy.
And that
is just one of the items
going together
for the burger.
Yes.
Next up?
We're gonna grind
our meat for our burger.
I use pancetta, short rib,
and strip steak.
So just a random mix
of this.
Yep.
No seasoning
going into this?
No.
So that's one grind.
Now we're gonna grind it
again.
What size patty?
8 ounce.
Burger's down.
We're gonna dredge
our fried green tomato.
Seasoned flour.
A little egg wash.
Panko.
And that's
all she wrote?
all she wrote.
Toasted bun. Jam is done.
Time to have fun.
Some goat cheese.
Fried green tomato.
Bacon jam.
And just
some mixed greens.
Bun.
There you go!
Think I can believe
George Washington came here
if he had this burger.
[ Grunts ]
Loosen up.
This is just riddled
with great flavor and balance.
You got this tangy,
sour goat cheese
with this sweet, unctuous,
crunchy bacon jam,
nice acidity coming in
from the fried green tomato.
That's kind of like
a composed steak dinner
shoved into a burger.
You are a dangerous man,
Captain Caveman.
[ Laughs ]
That's ridiculous.
Great burger.
The best burger
I've ever had.
There's nothing like
a Jersey tomato in the summer.
This is a good friend of mine,
Rebecca Brooks.
She's our PR agent
for Knuckle Sandwich
with her two boys.
How's the burger?
We got freshness
with the greens on the top,
sweet from the bacon
and chutney,
and tangy from the goat cheese
on the bottom,
which really cuts, like,
the gaminess from the meat.
What do you guys have, like,
food talk at home, Rebecca?
We do.
I definitely love eating
at the Rocky Hill Inn.
What, an hour from the city?
Worth the journey?
Where's the nearest
train stop?
'Cause I'm gonna come here
every day for lunch.
MAN: What Chef Evan's done
with the menu --
this place should be here
another 200 years.
It's a funky joint with a lot
of history and a great chef.
Well done.
Thank you.
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
to some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
You work here?
No?
You can't talk
with your mouth full?
Okay, I'll wait till
you're done.
[ Whistling ]
You ready to go?
[ Chuckling ]
Hey. Thumbs up.