Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins,
and dives.
This trip...
Drop the clutch.
...we're taking an eclectic road
to Flavortown.
I just want
to eat it all.
With some twists
and turns along the way.
I'm doing exactly
what you're doing.
You gotta
be kidding me.
Like a decades-old
family joint...
Mm!
You'll love this.
...cooking classic Creole
right in the heart of L.A.
It's like a little hidden
gem in the neighborhood.
Yeah.
And a Minneapolis butcher...
The turkey was dynamite,
but the pastrami is legit.
...cranking out cold
cuts minus the meat.
I'm impressed.
I'm trippin'.
And in Maui...
Getting after it,
aren't ya?
...a funky noodle joint...
Delicious.
Really,
really delicious.
...serving up something
that just rocked my world.
Whoa!
New favorite!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
You know how I
always say slow down
and take a look around?
Well, that might not apply
for this next
"Triple D" location.
Well, unless you're in Maui
over on the west side
in Lahaina.
And you happen to be
driving through some random
industrial park,
and you're looking
for a fantastic place
that scratch makes
all their noodles.
Well, then you're in luck
because this is Star Noodle.
How's that
frijole?
It's just got it,
you know.
It's just amazing.
Picking up
kimchi wings.
I love
this place.
One of the best
restaurants in the island.
Hey, guys. Bacon and eggs
here for you.
When we arrive,
it's kind of unpack
and rush to Star Noodle.
FIERI: But it's not just
for tourists.
When Michael Moore
opened in 2010,
he knew how to draw
in the locals, as well.
We wanted food that local people
especially knew about,
but we try to amp it up
a little bit.
I need tempura.
Asian-inspired,
Island, Pacific Rim.
You have the
"Hapa Ramen" here.
The ramen
is wonderful.
The pork inside
is tender.
And they make
their own noodles.
FIERI: Chef Ivan Pahk preps
the scratch-made dough,
and Lorilei Aloha Aguiar fires
up the 80-year-old
Japanese noodle machine.
Oh, I want one.
FIERI: All right,
let's get into it.
Over here,
we just have water.
Egg whites,
salt, sugar,
and potassium
carbonate.
That's gonna give it the chew,
that stretchy part.
All right, Lori, he got me
through the real difficult part
of mixing
everything together.
Oh, totally.
But now
he says
that the pro
has to come in.
So you take the flour
and the wheat gluten,
put it in the hopper,
turn it on.
Drop the clutch.
Pour the liquid.
Okay, so everything's in there.
How long is that gonna mix?
Three minutes. Then we put
the crumbles in the sheeter.
We got the gauges
all good.
Organize
the flux capacitor.
And then we roll it
through to make a sheet,
and we put it back up
on the roll.
And then we're gonna go
into the cutting process.
Mm-hmm.
That's beautiful.
Let's go cook those, Chef.
You ready?
Yep.
So we're gonna brine the pork
for the Hapa Ramen.
Water. Garlic. Maui onion, salt,
green onion palms.
Peppercorns,
brown sugar, honey,
bay leaf, ginger,
and lemongrass.
Oh.
Bring this
to a boil.
Okay
And then we'll
pour it right in here.
Shock it.
After we shock it,
then we squeeze the lemon,
and we pour
it right in.
And this is gonna marinate
for 24 hours?
24 hours.
Then we
roast it off.
375 for 1 hour.
Then we cover it,
then 300 for another 2 hours.
And then low and slow.
Got it.
Okay, Chef.
Roasted cold pork butt.
Break it apart,
we cut it into chunks.
And we want a lot
of that fat.
That's part
of the deal.
Enriches the dish.
So then we resteam it.
Okay. Next up, that's
the ramen that we made.
Yeah.
Now we take some
of the steamed pork.
In the broth, oh.
And then we get
some kamaboko.
And what is kamaboko?
Fish cake?
Fish cake.
Bamboo shoots
that we stewed down
in soy sauce
and dashi.
Okay.
A bunch
of green onion.
Some blanched
bok choy.
And then your favorite.
A soft-boiled egg.
Yeah, you're
real funny, Chef.
[ Laughs ]
And then we put
the pork stock.
So the pork stock is
an emulsification of fat.
We got pork bones,
a bunch of vegetables,
some apples,
Chinese cabbage.
You pour it -- Oh!
Two more things
we gotta put on there.
The aka miso, which is miso,
some soybean,
some sugar,
we cook it down.
And then we have mayu, which
is garlic and sesame paste.
That's our signature
bowl of noodles.
It's a funky little joint
next to a boatyard,
and you're making
this kind of food.
Delicious.
Really, really delicious.
I love the noodles.
Fantastic texture.
I love all the goodies
that you put along there,
the bamboo shoots, the bok choy.
The pork is great.
It's tender,
a little fatty,
lots of flavor
in it.
But that broth, homey --
outrageous.
Pick up Hapa.
So many different explosions
of flavor mixed together.
I just want to eat it all,
but I can't.
I'll be asleep.
There's more show
to do.
FIERI:
And more menu to dig into.
Vietnamese crepe.
Pork
with shrimp mixture.
Super-good herbs,
a really nice crunch.
Crepes in an Asian
noodle joint?
Now, that's something
I gotta try,
when we come back.
Welcome back.
We're hanging out here
on the west side
of Maui
at a funky joint
called Star Noodle.
Now, I can guarantee, you would
never drive by the place
'cause it's kind of
on the dead-end side
of an industrial park.
Mm-hmm.
So you will need to
get directions, but trust me.
It is so worth it.
Lots of different flavors
to try every time you come in.
We have our Vietnamese
crepe here.
The Vietnamese crepe
probably are our favorite.
The inside
is pork and shrimp,
and the outside
is a crunchy shell.
He makes a lettuce wrap
out of it with lovely herbs.
It's delicious.
Get after it,
Chef.
So, we got
some hot water,
and then
some rice flour.
So, that'll batter up
pretty good right off the bat.
Then got some cold water,
some salt.
Turmeric.
Really nice
color in this.
Your favorite.
Yes, please,
more.
And then we got
some limestone.
Limestone?
Limestone.
It makes
it super crispy.
Then we're gonna
immersion-blend it.
So we got a hot pan.
So, while that's cooking,
we're gonna do the filling.
So we get
some loco pork.
Some loco pork?
Mm-hmm.
Crazy pig.
So let's do
a shallow fry.
[ Sizzling ]
What are you putting in there,
before it burns both of us?
The shallow fry.
Shallow fry,
thanks a lot
for letting me know, homey.
[ Laughs ]
See,
folks at home,
when you have water
in the pan,
which that batter
has a ton of it,
and then you add
some more hot oil to it,
they don't
like each other.
Is that gonna get crunchy
like a wonton?
Yeah.
That crepe
just dancing in there.
Okay, so frying
off the pork.
Add a little bit of salt,
white pepper,
a little garlic,
some fish sauce, coconut milk.
Shrimp.
You're getting
after it, aren't you?
Okay, now, we're gonna add
the fresh bean sprouts.
Okay.
And some fresh
green onion.
Now we're ready to flip.
Look at that.
I've seen a lot.
This is a new one
for me.
So then
we take it out.
And it goes
with the salad here.
Yeah.
The filling.
I don't know.
I'm doing exactly
what you're doing.
You gotta be kidding me.
How is he gonna eat that?
So it's almost like
a lettuce wrap.
We cut it, grab a lettuce,
some of the filling.
Couple of the crunchies, herbs,
and we put the sauce.
I think we're gonna draw the
line at you feeding me, okay?
Okay. Okay.
Oh! New favorite.
The word crepe
completely throws it off.
It's crunchy.
The shrimp, the bean sprout.
Love the bean sprout in there.
Having the Thai
basil available
and the cilantro,
the crepe.
I want to have
crepe chips.
Mm. Mm, mm!
It's so good that,
if this was the only thing
you got to come
and have to eat
in your whole visit to Hawaii,
it'd be worth it.
Mm! God,
that's good!
Crepe going
in the window, Chef. Herb.
It's an amazing dish.
It's my favorite.
This might be in the top
25 most unique items
I've ever seen
on "Triple D."
Pick it up
"Look Moore Fun"
Love this place.
Do lunch and dinner here,
it's really that good.
You have lunch, go to the beach,
you come back for dinner.
It's the best.
The first time
you have this, I promise you,
you will
not forget it.
You're the bomb.
Nice job.
Thank you, Chef.
FIERI: Coming up, a real-deal
taste of New Orleans...
Oh, I'll just sit here
and eat it all day.
...cooked up in Los Angeles
for generations.
This is
old school right here.
You know, on "Triple D,"
we have featured just about
every type of food
you can imagine.
But one that we don't do
nearly enough, Creole and Cajun.
So, guess where I'm at?
I'm in Los Angeles, California,
in the Jefferson Park
neighborhood to check out
a joint that I've been to before
and you're gonna love.
This is Harold & Belle's.
One jambalaya.
Just totally unlike anything
else you'll find in L.A.
I have catfish nuggets
for the gentleman.
MAN: You want a touch
or a taste of New Orleans,
Harold & Belle's is
the place to come.
This restaurant has been
in the same family
for 47 years.
FIERI: Going back to 1969,
when Louisiana transplants
Harold and
Mary Belle Legaux opened
a dive bar
serving up gumbo and po'boys.
Now five decades
and two renovations later,
grandson Ryan's still
cooking up the Creole.
All four of my grandparents
are from New Orleans.
I have a very Creole
last name, Legaux.
L-e-g-a-u-x.
The only people
that have "X" in their name
are people
that come from Louisiana.
Right.
I don't find much Cajun Creole
food in the West Coast,
so when I came here
and I met this guy
and I tried the food, I'm like,
you're the real deal, brother.
Large gumbo.
The gumbo's
one of my favorite dishes.
Sausage, chicken, crab.
When I think
of making true gumbo,
I'm thinking
of all the goods.
All right, buddy,
fire it up.
Seafood stock.
Okay.
What we're gonna do
next is put in our trinity.
In the French cooking,
you have mirepoix,
which is the onions
and celery and the carrots,
and in Creole cooking,
you have the peppers,
the celery, and the onions.
Have you ever heard
the term filet gumbo?
This is the ground-up
sassafras leaf.
Creole seasoning.
Ground thyme,
ground basil,
dried parsley flakes.
More black pepper.
We had some in our Creole
seasoning already.
We like more.
More granulated onion,
more granulated garlic.
Okay.
I'm gonna
let that cook down,
and then we're gonna
add our roux. Thicken it up.
all that in there?
Most of it.
The roux's the key, baby.
Next up.
Some boneless/skinless
chicken thighs, seasoned with...
Harold and Belle's
Creole seasoning.
Beef hot links.
Diced pit ham.
Smoked sausage.
Really key.
You know, a lot of recipes
in New Orleans,
they use andouille,
which is like a combination.
Right.
Spicy and smoke,
so we just do it
with two different sausages.
Blue crab. This is another key
for the flavor.
I'm gonna let this cook
for probably about 45 minutes.
In the last 15 minutes before
service, we'll drop the shrimp?
We'll drop
the shrimp in there.
Okay.
Oh,
it looks fantastic.
All right, Guy.
You ready for some gumbo?
Do it.
Make sure we get you some blue
crab and some shrimp on there.
A little parsley.
Look at
this gumbo.
It's not thin
like stock.
It's not heavy
like stew.
Mm.
That's fantastic.
You pick up that seafood.
Even though there was
just a little bit
of that blue crab,
you get --
Mm!
Velvety texture
coming over your tongue
from that sassafras,
getting it from that roux.
Right.
Oh, I'll just sit here
and eat it all day.
A small filet gumbo.
MAN: The gumbo
is amazing.
The spices,
the flavor.
This
is Tara and Cara.
Tara's
on the culinary team
for
"Guy's Grocery Games."
And this is Cara,
who's actually
one of our editors
and helps develop the show.
So, since you both
have such wide-range
knowledge of the food,
take it away.
So, the gumbo here
has two types of sausage.
And one's
light and fluffy,
and the other's
got, like, a nice bite.
I love both.
Having a little bit
of soul
and a little bit of spice
in the heart of L.A.
is a nice balance.
MAN: Jefferson Park area
was a stopping-off point
for a lot of people
that had moved from Louisiana,
and Harold & Belle's was
kind of an anchor
for people
to come together.
It's like a little hidden gem
in the neighborhood.
Yeah, I wouldn't even
know it was here.
Good buddy of mine, Walt,
one of our camera guys
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
Tell me what you think
of the food.
It's incredible.
Crawfish étouffée ready.
Shrimp and crawfish smothered
in this beautiful gravy sauce.
Okay, now we're
into the étouffée.
Right,
we start with the roux.
Canola and olive oil.
Once the oil's hot,
we're gonna stir in our flour.
We want this roux to kind
of be a brownish color,
kind of like the color
of peanut butter.
When the roux is
at the temperature
we want it at,
we're gonna add our trinity.
Our red and green bell peppers,
our onions, and our celery.
Correct. Harold & Belle's
Creole seasoning,
ground bay leaf,
minced garlic,
hot sauce,
granulated garlic,
and more paprika,
cayenne pepper, not too much.
We have
some ground basil...
Okay.
...some parsley flakes,
some black pepper.
Worcestershire?
Yes, sir.
A little bit of
extra Creole seasoning.
We're gonna
stir it all in.
The roux's starting
to tighten up.
We're gonna add
some tomato soup.
I don't know that
I've seen tomato soup,
but I'll give it
to you.
Shrimp stock.
Okay.
Let this simmer
for about an hour.
And then...
We're gonna
add our crawfish.
Ah, that's gonna work
for me.
Let that cook down, get
the crawfish flavor in there.
About a half-hour
is all you need for that.
Then we're gonna add
the cream of mushroom soup.
And that's how it was
made 40 years ago?
This is old school
right here.
We cool it down and then
heat it up to order.
'Cause if you held it hot,
it would just sit there
and continue
to cook down.
Extra crawfish tails.
Our étouffée is nice and hot.
Gonna put it in a bowl
for you, Guy.
We'll just put
a little parsley on there.
Tight
but not too tight.
Mm. My buddy Kim Gardner --
and this dude's Cajun.
Kim, what's up, buddy?
Uh, and this is the first time
I had real étouffée.
And there's so much flavor
going on in this.
All the spices, I mean,
you are just talking deep
and rich and creamy.
And you get nice, little,
tender crawfish inside of it.
Crawfish is an intensified
shrimp flavor
and a great, meaty texture,
kind of like lobster.
Mmm!
You'll love this.
Shrimp and crawfish
étouffée.
Really, really
incredible crawfish.
It's spicy,
but not too spicy.
It always delivers
every time you come.
You're sticking
to the traditions.
You're upgrading
the program where you can,
and you really
embody this.
You really celebrate it.
Fantastic.
This guy.
FIERI:
Up next in Minneapolis...
That's crazy.
...this deli's
laying it on thick.
You own this.
But you won't believe
what they're leaving out.
This is, like, groundbreaking
stuff here, bud.
So, what the show
is called
is "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives,"
but what it really is,
it's just a trip to Flavortown.
We're looking
for real food
by real people
all across the country,
and now
all around the world.
So here we are
in Minneapolis, Minnesota,
to check out the one and the
only that I've ever heard of.
This is
the Herbivorous Butcher.
Sliced meats
everywhere.
I need some jerky.
But, of course,
it's all plant-based.
This is the only vegan butcher
shop I've ever been to.
I feel like they're
changing the world.
But for siblings
Aubrey and Kale Walch,
it all started with
very personal changes
back in their teens.
For me, it was
for ethical reasons.
Ethical reasons.
Yeah, for me,
it was for health.
Health reasons.
My nickname
was butterball.
FIERI: So they started making
meat-free meats
and cheese-free cheeses,
first selling at local
farmers markets in 2014,
and then, less than
two years later,
had their own
takeout joint.
They want people
who eat meat to say,
"This looks like what
I'm used to eating,
and I can still eat it
and enjoy it."
CHEF:
Turkey dill Havarti!
The turkey sandwich
tastes amazing.
So, what are we
gonna make first?
This'll be
the vegan turkey.
I'll start with
the vital wheat gluten.
It's a 95%
protein flour.
This is traditional
yeast flakes, some onion powder.
And these are recipes
that you just developed.
Yes. We've got sea salt,
and this is some thyme.
It's some thyme.
When is it gonna
get the turkey flavor?
A lot of it comes from
housemade chicken broth powder.
We take nutritional yeast,
thyme, sage, turmeric,
salt, mix it with water.
Just like Mom
used to make.
Instant flavor.
Got some olive oil
so it
doesn't turn out
like a sponge.
Soy sauce for a little
bit more depth.
We're gonna pour
the liquid in there.
This is the turkey.
We will wrap it
in its cheesecloth home here.
What do we do
with that?
This goes into boiling water
for about an hour and a half.
Cooks it
all the way through.
Bake it for another
ten minutes.
Dries it out
a little bit.
Then we add some soy sauce
and olive oil on top of it.
To give
it a little texture.
Yeah.
Give a little color
to the outside.
Yep.
And then you go
and slice it from there.
Slice it ready.
So, this is your deli
meat right here.
That's
the deli turkey.
It's got texture.
It's moist, and it's not rubber,
and it's not a sponge.
I'm impressed.
I'm trippin'.
Let's do
the cheese.
What are we
making now?
Dill Havarti.
We start with
the coconut oil base,
soy milk, lemon juice
in a white wine vinegar.
It helps to emulsify it.
Put that in a blender.
Next up.
We got tapioca
flour, Kappa carrageenan,
so it's
a seaweed.
Oh. I was..
It helps solidify
the cheese.
Nutritional yeast flakes,
sea salt.
And that's
the white miso.
That's basically
the flavor foundation.
Pretty much.
Onto the stove.
It's fresh dill.
Heated up.
Thicken it up.
It cools in
the fridge overnight,
and then it solidifies
into a solid block.
Wow.
That's crazy.
Okay, make a sandwich?
All right, yeah.
Let's do it.
We've got
our garlic mayo.
Got dijon mustard,
throw some turkey on there.
[ Whistles ]
The dill Havarti, best part --
throw some lettuce on here.
Tomatoes and ze onion.
All right.
Jump in.
I'd eat it
all day long.
[ Laughs ]
Fresh veggies,
a good amount of moisturizer
with the vegan mayo.
We're eating it
on a fantastic roll.
You definitely get
the creaminess of the cheese.
You get that chew,
you get that texture,
that meaty texture
coming through from the turkey.
Fantastic.
We got a line
out here.
It's so good.
The dill Havarti
is off the hook.
The turkey is flavored
really well.
MAN:
The texture of the feel,
everything about it
is just like meat.
How do you get different
textures in different meats?
It's different ratios,
and we use
different bean flours
to create
different textures.
This is like, groundbreaking,
stuff here, bud.
Yeah, well,
we're trying.
FIERI: And wait till you
see the texture
he's mixing up for
the three meats on this monster.
Italian cold cut
is amazing.
Just packed with
so many good things.
KALE: This is one of my
pride and joys.
So you're saying
the turkey was dynamite,
but the pastrami
is legit.
It's my favorite.
Tomato juice, Liquid Smoke,
got some water.
Next up -- soy sauce.
Plenty of olive oil.
Pastrami is
a nice, juicy meat.
Tomato paste.
Lots of garlic.
White miso.
Next dry ingredients --
vital wheat gluten,
nutritional yeast flakes,
red beet powder.
Gives it a nice color,
a little sweetness.
This is agar-agar.
Another seaweed
like carrageenan.
Agar-agar?
Agar-agar.
Yeah.
They just couldn't use
one agar?
No, it's so good,
they had to name it twice.
Ground mustard.
You've got basil and oregano.
Smoked paprika,
sea salt, onion powder,
and the fennel
and peppercorns.
Mix all this together.
Wow. Okay.
Right in.
Looks like ground beef.
Crazy.
Throw it on here. This will
all go into the steamer?
Yep.
How long is it
gonna steam for?
Steams for an hour.
Bakes for another half-hour,
then you let it cool.
Bring it out,
and you slice from there.
Yep.
All right. Got that same garlic
mayo we put on the turkey.
Oregano,
salt, and pepper here.
Oh, I'm so excited.
So, we got that pastrami,
capicola, salty ham,
we got the pepperoni
in there, too.
And this is our mozzarella
cheese, lettuce.
Got some onions.
Red onion.
Cherry peppers,
oil and vinegar.
Let's see if I can
get this one shut.
You own this.
No way.
I'm picking up
the notes of the smoke.
the notes of the pepper.
There's a good fat amount.
It's not dry.
You're the Columbus
of this, man.
You guys are gonna dig it.
Trust me.
Delicious.
I, of course, drag one
of my buddies in on this.
My buddy
Craig Scanlon.
I could not believe the texture,
followed up with the flavor.
It tastes like
a cold cut Italian.
It's a little bit
of sweet and spicy.
They're definitely
onto something.
FIERI: I came here
with my own level of skepticism,
but I would not be
steering you wrong
telling you to come in here
and try this.
It's fantastic.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
So, was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
After we shock it,
then we squeeze the lemon in.
Shock it? Like,
as in Chaka Khan?
Like Shaka-shaka.
BOTH: Shaka!
[ Laughter ]