Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives.
This trip...
[ Laughing ] Yes!
...we're grabbing burgers,
bagels...
This should be illegal.
buns...
Sun's out, buns out.
Please get me a T-shirt
that says that.
...and something
called bacorn?
I swear, I have never heard
of this in my life.
That's at a Los Angeles
joint mashing up
Korean with
a little bit of Cali.
There's nothing about this
that I don't think is fantastic.
Plus,
two New Jersey brothers...
This dude
gets after it.
...who really know
their dough.
There's no way
I could keep up.
And a Portsmouth,
New Hampshire deli...
It's a small place
with big flavor.
...amped up and lights out.
That is outstanding.
That's all right here,
right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
You go to Texas, you better
find some real-deal brisket.
You head up to Seattle,
better be some fresh seafood.
Over to Chicago,
it's gotta be the bomb pizza.
So when you end up here
on the East Coast,
what should you expect?
That's right --
righteous bagels.
We're here in Plainsboro,
New Jersey.
And this is Bagel Street Grill.
Chicken Ruffino,
order up.
New Jersey definitely
knows good bagels.
SERVER: Turkey, lettuce,
tomato on sesame.
Everything
with cream cheese.
-That's a legit bagel?
-Legit.
-Best in the state.
-Seriously?
Absolutely,
100 percent.
FIERI: That's 'cause owners
and brothers
Jimmy and Doug Rohr have
been busting out bagels
since they were teenagers.
Part-time job
while we were in college.
And we were like,
"Wow, this is a great business.
Let's do it.
Let's do it ourselves."
FIERI:
So they opened their first joint
together back in 1988.
WOMAN: Can I help
the next person?
And they're still sticking
with the tried and true.
You have
to boil a bagel.
We do it
the old-fashioned way.
And they're putting out
some volume.
We do about 15,000 bagels
a week, 20 varieties.
Are there four other brothers
that do the work?
Two jalapeño cheddar bagels,
order up.
The jalapeño cheddar bagel
is my favorite.
A little bit spiced,
gotta be ready for it.
Okay, You've got, like,
the legit bagel equipment.
JIMMY: Yes. This is what you
need to produce a lot of them.
Give me the rundown,
Holmes.
First, we're gonna start
with a basic plain dough.
We start off with some sugar,
some salt there.
We're gonna put
our water in now.
"Watuh."
With some yeast.
And then turn around,
we're gonna grab
a bag of flour here.
[ Laughs ]
This is
a 50-pound dough.
How long will this go?
We got about
15 minutes.
In about 10 minutes,
we'll start throwing in
our jalapeños --
The jalapeños
and the cheddar.
And cheddar cheese.
Okay.
That thing's huge.
And you didn't even roast
the jalapeños or anything?
No, we want it
to kick.
-Yeah, the Jersey style, right?
-Yeah, that's it.
So now what happens?
I'm gonna cut equal strips
to put right
in this machine right here.
This first section's gonna
divide the dough
into equal portions.
It's gonna drop
onto this conveyor
and form the bagel.
Do they have
a home version of this?
'Cause I want one.
[ Laughing ] Right?
We're gonna run this
a little slow.
It goes faster than this?
Oh, yeah.
This thing makes
about 10,000 an hour
if you really crank
it up.
There's no way
I could keep up.
You got like 18 fingers, dude.
I'm already watching this.
I've done a few bagels
in my life.
No, you think?
And from here --
These'll proof
for 3 hours.
Then they go dark
for the night.
That's it.
And bake them first
thing in the morning.
All right.
Let's go.
First,
we boil our bagels.
Slide them in.
They've gotten puffy.
We're gonna transfer them
over on
to these kiln-dried
redwood boards.
This dude gets
after it.
This is kind of like angry,
hot-dough Tetris.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna put them
in the oven for about
3 minutes
on these boards.
What temp are we running at?
About 495.
Four ninety-five?
These are ready to flip?
The plastic gloves, again,
are gonna be your only --
No problem.
No fingers.
And how long are they gonna ride
the carousel of heat?
For about 20,
25 minutes in here now.
And we can do
12 dozen per shelf,
five shelves
in that oven.
That's 60 dozen.
Keep them going all day long.
[ Laughing ] Yep.
You're crazy.
[ Laughing ] Yes.
[ Laughing ] Yes!
There we go.
Look at that crust
on it.
We should cut it
first.
Do we toast it?
I like them toasted.
I wanna toast it.
I'll go veggie spread.
Vegetable cream cheese.
What's in it?
Scallions, carrots,
broccoli,
little bit of onion powder
in there.
Brother, I've had
a lot of jalapeño bagels.
And all they do is waft
the jalapeño over the top.
You get serious.
There's heat in that.
I mean, you can smell
the jalapeño.
That's dynamite.
To see the whole process
go through,
it makes you appreciate
it so much more.
That crust, that chew,
soft in the middle,
nice texture
on the outside.
Real deal, brother.
Real deal.
Jalapeño
with cream cheese.
It's got the perfect
crunch on the top.
WOMAN: The cheddar has, like,
a nice mildness to it
that counteracts
with the jalapeño.
I need
two Asiago bagels grilled.
So, probably my favorite
Neapolitan pizza chef
in the world is Roberto
from Don Antonio's
and Raphael,
his son-in-law.
So, brother, you lived
in New York City long enough.
You know good bagels.
Yes.
How are these bagels?
Amazing.
A bagel is very simple
but very similar
to Neapolitan pizza.
Absolutely.
Really good ingredients,
handle it
the right way,
have the right equipment
to cook it.
And if you don't mess with it,
it'll be perfect.
Oh, you're right.
It's very simple.
FIERI:
But A simple start doesn't mean
there isn't a big finish.
JIMMY: Pork roll loaded burger.
Order up.
Tater tots are on top
on an Asiago bagel.
The burger, it's got chunks
of pork roll built into it.
Pork roll's a type of ham
you can't get anywhere else.
It's a staple of New Jersey,
so why not put it in a burger?
You can't go anywhere
in New Jersey
and not find a breakfast
or lunch place
that doesn't have pork roll.
Everybody loves this.
All right, so what are we
gonna do with it?
We're gonna open
this thing up here
and dig into
that canvas.
You know it's good
when it's got canvas.
We're gonna cut about
a pound of this off.
It is cooked?
It is cooked.
We're going
to cube it up.
And then,
you're gonna fry it...
Yes.
...and then stuff it
into the burger?
Yes.
That's
deep-fried pork roll.
It tastes like a cross
between salami and bologna.
It's like bologna
with texture.
You nailed it.
All right.
Let's see what you do.
We start with
our chopped meat.
Gonna load it with
our pork roll, two eggs.
Minced garlic.
A bunch of it.
Worcestershire sauce.
Oh, yeah.
Onion powder, salt and pepper,
and bread crumbs.
Mix this up.
Patty it up.
Flattop.
And right alongside of it,
we're gonna grill
our Asiago bagel.
All right.
Top that with our
pork roll-loaded burger.
Gonna add our tater tots,
fresh outta the fryer,
our house-made
Thousand Island dressing.
What is wrong
with you?
This should be illegal.
But it's good.
You got salty, fatty,
an awesome bagel.
The little nuggets,
the pork roll,
you get your French fry
already built into it.
When you have
a bagel joint
and you wanna play mad scientist
and make something for people,
in the New Jersey area,
you love pork roll,
that's your burger.
SERVER: Pork roll burger.
The bagels make
the sandwich better.
FIERI: Have you ever had
pork roll?
Yeah, I have.
But it never
tasted like this.
Morning, guys.
It's very nice food
all the way around.
Just one more bite,
just one.
Just for the flavor.
Yeah. Nice job.
Thanks.
Wrap that to go.
FIERI: Coming up, a Los Angeles
spot loading up the buns...
You got people lining up
for that one.
...and putting out
one funky bar snack.
Where have I been that I did
not know about corn cheese?
And we were, like,
working in a --
a -- part -- uh, in --
for a bagel store.
Were you guys
in karate, too?
Yeah!
What was going on there?
So, I'm here in Koreatown
in Los Angeles
to check out a funky joint
called the Biergarten.
Wait, wait, wait --
the Biergarten?
No, that was years ago.
What am I thinking?
No, I'm directly
across the street
to check out a place
that started as a food truck
and then went full-blown
brick and mortar.
This is the Bun Shop.
It is delicious, man.
All right, guys.
You hungry?
It is a very cool, contemporary
take on Korean food.
Korean tacos.
WOMAN: Feels almost like
you're eating something
you shouldn't be eating
'cause it tastes so good.
Spicy pig buns
for service.
The food truck started
from two guys from Detroit.
James went to culinary school.
Brian was a businessman.
I was here first,
working corporate.
And he was
in New York.
I just called him up
on a whim and said,
"Would you wanna
start the truck?"
FIERI:
After a few years of earning
their cred on the streets,
high-school buddies
James Seok and Brian Yeun
set up a permanent shop
in 2014.
SERVER: Temp veg bun.
WOMAN: Not many food trucks
make it to brick.
But Bun Shop is
the place
that you chase down
because of the food.
Can we fire up
five buns, please?
The bun is actually, like,
super-soft Wonder Bread.
It's light, sticky.
YEUN:
It's a Chinese bao bun.
So you bring the buns
in from a Chinese baker
that knows how
to make great bun.
-And you don't reinvent it.
-That's right.
FIERI: You just get to decide
what to put it in.
Kalbi buns for service.
WOMAN: The kalbi beef bun,
it's got such a good
traditional Korean taste.
Very sweet and savory
at the same time.
All right, brother.
Where are we at? Talk to me.
We're here to do
our kalbi bun.
We start with the onion
and garlic purée.
And what type of meat
are you using?
It's a nice beef strip.
We let this sit for about
an hour to tenderize it.
Now we'll go
into the marinade.
Puréed ginger,
puréed garlic,
white sugar,
brown sugar.
This is
our cider vinegar.
So this is not too traditional
of a kalbi marinade.
-Oh, really?
-Yes.
No, I didn't know,
with the apple cider vinegar
jumping in there.
We got toasted sesame oil,
some corn syrup,
soy sauce, room-temp water,
apple soda.
Apple soda?
And then some cola.
Some cola?
Yes, sir.
Very, very
traditional.
Mix it up.
Make sure the sugar
somewhat dissolves in there.
Put that on
a bath mat.
That pours over
the tenderized meat.
After the marinade
has been
sitting in there
for about 24 hours,
take some canola oil,
kalbi beef that we marinated.
Let it go here a solid minute,
minute and a half.
What's up next?
Spicy aioli.
We'll start with our mayo,
sour cream --
Corn syrup?
You don't see corn syrup
much anymore.
It's a Korean thing,
I think.
Sambal?
Yep, Sambal, Sriracha,
garlic paste, honey.
And a little sesame oil?
Toasted sesame oil.
Looks like Thousand Island,
tastes like...
Korean Thousand Island.
[ Laughs ]
All right.
Steam the bun.
About 3 minutes.
So we take our steamed buns
here, line the bottom
with our homemade
spicy aioli
with a layer
of our mixed greens.
Put our freshly cooked
kalbi beef.
-My mouth's starting to --
-Oh, yeah.
And then we have a tempura fried
onion over here.
Of course you do.
Yes, sir.
Oh, that's good.
The bun is not super-doughy.
It's a great vessel.
Kinda like a really good
handmade flour tortilla.
Marinade on the meat is not
too sweet, not too gingery.
The spicy aioli really
counterbalances everything.
Has a good yin and yang.
I can see why it's
your signature. It's fantastic.
Thank you, sir.
Really good.
Kalbi buns
for service.
That beef has just got that
great Korean barbecue flavor.
What about the bun?
MAN: It's very soft.
It really blends it
all together.
Katsu bun
in the window.
The Bun Shop has a lot
of different options for people
who may not know
that much about Korean food.
Spicy pig buns
for service.
The spicy pig is really good.
It has a nice kick.
All right, Chef.
We got our spicy pig.
This is the one with that
tzatziki sauce in it, homemade.
Korean Greek.
Oh, it's nice and tender.
Nice spice, great pork.
-Thank you, sir.
-So tell me about this one.
Two temp veg buns.
The tempura vegetable one
is more veggie-style.
And I love
the fried avocado.
We've got a jalapeño cilantro
aioli inside the bottom,
fresh tomato,
our grilled onions,
and then our tempura fried
avocado with cilantro.
You got people
lining up for that one.
I mean,
we're in California.
We gotta do something
with avocado.
Delicious.
Thank you, sir.
The temp veg
is truly my favorite.
The tempura and the avocado,
throwing it with veggies
and wrapping it in a bun.
Only in California.
FIERI: But I don't know where
this dish is coming from.
Service
for bacorn cheese.
FIERI: Bacorn?
So that's your play
on bacon and corn.
Yeah. Corn cheese is, like,
a pretty traditional bar snack.
Corn cheese?
Yes, sir.
We add our bacon to it.
We have to.
Where have I been that I
do not know about corn cheese?
If they're serving
cheesy corn, I'm in.
FIERI: Definitely sign me up,
too, when we come back.
FIERI:
"Triple D" is at full steam
in Koreatown, Los Angeles,
at a neighborhood spot,
the Bun Shop.
Katsu and temp veg
for service.
FIERI: When people are looking
for good buns,
this is where they come?
Sun's out, buns out.
Please get me a T-shirt
that says that.
FIERI: But despite the name,
buns aren't the only thing
on the menu here.
Bacorn cheese right here.
Bacon and corn and cheese --
it's really unique.
I've never seen the bacorn
in any other restaurant.
FIERI: But Chef James
tells me corn cheese
is a common
Korean bar food snack.
They traditionally
call it an anju.
And they put their own spin
on it here.
I swear, I have never
heard of this in my life.
It is a little skillet
full of yumminess.
-Okay, bacorn cheese.
-Okay.
Wok is on.
This wok,
just so you know,
we are, like, at
60,000, 80,000 BTUs.
So we're gonna start off
with some butter here.
Throw our chopped bacon in,
chopped jalapeños.
Another Korean item.
Yeah. Well, you know...
We're in L.A.
Go with our sweet corn,
a little bit of garlic here,
scallions.
Bacorn cheese.
Salt and pepper.
Toss it up.
Oh, look at you work
the wok.
Yes, sir.
That's just sexy
in itself.
Can I get that
in slo-mo, please?
Yeah, that's what
I'm talking about.
This is condensed milk
and mayo.
Condensed milk
and mayonnaise?
This is like a bar food snack
type of thing.
So mozzarella --
Another one of my
favorite fine Korean items.
Of course.
Get this
well incorporated here.
And then, we'll top it off
with the rest of
our mozzarella here.
Then it goes in
the salamander?
Goes in the salamander,
get a nice color on there.
30, 45 seconds.
Korean dish.
[ Laughs ]
Come out of
the salamander here.
Scallions here.
And it's ready to go.
When did Korea
hit Alabama?
[ Laughs ]
There's nothing
about this
that I don't think is
fantastic.
It's creamy,
a little sweet,
a little salt to the bacon,
really good corn.
It pops.
Not overly cheesy,
not overly salty.
Not overly anything.
It's a great dish.
But I've never seen
anything like it.
Do you know a chef
named Damaris Phillips?
She's one of my judges
on "Guy's Grocery Games,"
quite the Southern chef.
If this is not
Damaris 101,
Louisville, Kentucky,
corn dish,
I wouldn't know
what is.
Excellent.
Thank you, Chef.
Bacorn for service.
I have never, ever,
ever had anything like it.
Very flavorful
and really good.
Mama wings for service.
The Bun Shop allows you to have
a new, contemporary experience
but also enjoy
the traditional flavors
of Korean culture.
Awesome.
Congratulations.
Happy for you.
Thank you, sir.
FIERI: Up next,
a New Hampshire spot
claiming to be a deli.
You guys have got
a lot going on here.
But what I'm finding here --
well, it's a whole lot more.
The only thing wrong
with that dish,
there's not another nine ribs
connected to it.
So I'm here in downtown
Portsmouth, New Hampshire,
about a third of a mile
from the Piscataqua River
to check out a joint
where a chef from New Jersey
and a chef from Connecticut,
well, they migrated north
and opened up
a not-so-common deli.
This is the Kitchen.
The Meatball Diavolo.
The food's delicious.
Just amazing flavor.
Plating the Angelina.
It's hard to walk by
without coming in.
FIERI:
Been that way since 2011,
when owners and restaurant vets
Matt Greco and Mike Prete
brought some bold flavors
into this little port town.
Bolognese pizza
in the window.
It's a New York-style deli
on steroids.
Tuscan up.
FIERI: 'Cause while the menu's
loaded with sandwiches...
SERVER: Turkey club.
...they aren't serving this dish
at any deli I know.
Kitchen ribs.
This, right here,
is a meal for me.
They fall off the bone, melt in
your mouth. They're delicious.
What are we into?
So we're gonna
brine our ribs.
First up -- water,
red wine vinegar,
juniper berries,
kosher salt,
black pepper --
Fresh-ground?
Fresh-ground.
Brown sugar, dried thyme,
dried dill,
star anise, garlic,
red pepper flake.
Then we mix
this all up.
St. Louis-style rib.
So what we did is
took a spare rib.
It's cut down so it's
in a uniform shape.
And I see you got a little
flap meat on there, too?
Yep.
All right.
We leave that all on.
Fantastic.
Love the brine.
Pork and vinegar just
go so hand-in-hand.
This is gonna brine
overnight.
Next step, we're gonna make
our barbecue rub.
So we got smoked paprika,
seasoning salt,
ground black pepper,
brown sugar,
get a little caramelization
on it,
chili powder and ginger,
ground ginger.
Just mix that up.
So these have been
down for 24 hours.
24 hours.
I'm gonna need a little bit
of that brine.
Just so
there's some liquid.
Then we're gonna take
our barbecue rub
and just rub them down.
So you're building
a little bit of the bark.
And this will go
into the oven, 350,
for about 2 hours.
I'm gonna portion them up,
single bone.
Little more of the rub.
Put those right
on our grill.
That's a nice,
meaty rib.
They get a nice,
little caramelization to them,
heated right through.
We're gonna put some
of our agrodolce sauce on it.
Agrodolce --
a little sweet and sour.
Actually, ours is
a little more sweet and spicy.
Little molasses.
We'll plate these up.
Give you a little more sauce
because if you're eating ribs
and you're not licking
your fingers, there's
something wrong.
We'll give you
a little green.
I'm a big vinegar fan.
So when I saw that on the menu,
I thought,
"Okay.
I wanna get after this."
It totally delivers
there.
The dry rub is also
really on point.
But the kicker
is this agrodolce sauce.
You have your red pepper
and vinegar and...
Little garlic.
Garlicky.
The only thing wrong
with that dish,
there's not another nine ribs
connected to it.
That is outstanding.
Kitchen ribs up.
Nice little bark on top,
great flavors.
MAN: Anybody that tells you
you have to go down south
for good ribs
is sadly mistaken.
All the food here
is super-fresh.
And the flavors
are very unique.
FIERI: So are the names.
Franky Boom Bahtz
and the Eh Yo Mikey burger.
Plus, there's this lamb burger
with an Indian twist.
SERVER: The Apu burger.
The Apu burger.
The what?
Apu from "The Simpsons."
WOMAN: The mix of the chutneys
and the cheese
and the Indian spices --
so amazing.
FIERI:
What are we making first?
We're gonna make the mango
chutney for the Apu burger.
Put a little oil
in our pan.
We're gonna throw in shallots,
jalapeño, red bell pepper,
crushed fennel in there.
Great.
Kosher salt,
some curry powder
and black pepper.
We're gonna add
our mango.
Canned?
These are frozen mango.
Sweat these down
a little bit,
get some of those flavors
coming outta there.
Got some orange juice.
Apple cider vinegar,
brown sugar.
Cook down for
about 15 minutes.
I love it.
Then we're gonna finish it
with chopped lychee
and some poppy seed,
just to add some color.
Let that sit overnight.
All right.
Lamb burger.
Pat it down.
We season it
with our lamb seasoning,
which is garam masala,
salt and pepper.
Got it. Okay.
We're gonna let
that go.
What temperature
are we cooking that to?
We're gonna go medium.
While that's going,
we'll get our bun going.
This is
our brioche onion.
Locally made?
Yep.
We're gonna take
our cilantro lime mayo,
put this
right on top of the bun,
the mango chutney --
Ground pistachios.
That's a nice touch.
Come over
to our feta cheese.
Funky with the feta.
We just give it
a little dusting on the cheese
with our lamb seasoning.
Our lamb burger's
ready to go.
Finish it with
a little fresh cilantro.
And there you go.
Heck of a burger.
Lots of great juice
coming out of that.
It's a picture-perfect
funky lamb burger.
It's rich,
perfectly seasoned.
The garam masala --
spot-on.
I thought it was gonna be
too much feta. By no means.
Chutney adds that --
that big array of sweetness
that you need,
the balance
to the feta.
Mmm. That's one of the better
lamb burgers I've ever had.
It's a great mix of flavors
that, usually,
you wouldn't expect.
Have you had
this lamb burger before?
-It's amazing.
-It's redunkulous.
So a couple of our partners
in crime with No Kid Hungry,
this is Alisha and Emily.
As great as a super country
as we are,
we still have kids going to
school hungry every single day.
About one in five kids
in this country struggle
with hunger.
Here in the Northeast,
we work really closely
with the New Hampshire
Food Bank.
And there are sites
where kids can go
and they can get
a healthy meal.
How do they get
more information?
Nokidhungry.org,
and everyone can go.
And everyone has
the strength to share.
That's awesome,
what you guys are doing.
Have you been
to the Kitchen before?
I come here literally
every time I come to Portsmouth.
WOMAN:
It's wholesome, fresh.
And it's what
I really love to eat.
You guys have got
a lot going on here.
I mean, it's a small place
with big flavor.
Outstanding, Chef.
Thank you.
Well done.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
Anybody drop 5 bucks?
Five bucks?
You dropped 5 bucks?
There you go.