Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you ridin' shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown!
This is "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives"!
-This trip...
-Here we go!
FIERI:
We're breakin' out the bird.
It's sturdy as I get dirty.
...and sharin' in the feast.
This is my kinda church.
Like at a bakery cafe
in Somersworth, New Hampshire...
Mmm, that's good.
...puttin' poultry into
a comfort classic.
We're talkin' about a big
hot turkey meatloaf sandwich.
And at a community café
in Louisville...
-Okay, time to eat.
-Time to eat!
FIERI: ...where payin' it
forward is their daily special.
This is a place
you wanna visit.
Plus, in Princeton,
New Jersey...
Things are gettin' gnarly!
...Rev Run is in the house.
That tastes like wow!
FIERI: ...for crepes that are
definitely jammin'.
We 'bout to do this like Brutus
'cause we ain't new to this.
That's fantastic.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
Don't look at me.
This is Rev Run's territory.
Yo, Guy! We're here
in Princeton, New Jersey.
You know I like to jam, right?
Ha ha!
Well, this is Jammin' Crepes.
Boom!
Brownies in a blanket up!
Everything that we've ever
ordered here is incredible.
Peach chutney on the club.
Everything reflects
their mission
to bring fresh and local
ingredients to their food.
FIERI: A mission owners
Kim and Amin Rizk,
along with Kathy Klockenbrink,
launched with their fruit,
veggie, and meat-filled crepes.
We started at
the farmer's market
and really started
cooking the crepes,
um, as a street food.
-She calls it a "crep."
-Crepe.
-Crepe. No more "crape."
FIERI: However you say it,
it was a hit.
So after three years,
they grew from market
to brick-and-mortar.
What's the smash?
What's the number one hit?
"Walk This Way"
or "Tricky" is mine.
Yeah.
What's your "Walk This Way"?
What's your "Tricky"?
It's our Jammin' Turkey Club.
The turkey club
is one of my favorites.
-What's in it?
-Okay.
So we're gonna make
our peach chutney.
Okay.
Fresh peaches from an orchard
just two miles down the road.
Chopped Walla Walla
onion from a local farm.
-Walla Walla onions.
-Walla Walla.
Yellow bell pepper.
Dried pineapple.
Crystallized ginger.
-Fresh garlic.
-Jalapeño. Fantastic.
Cider vinegar.
-Light brown sugar.
-Chili flake.
Really good cinnamon.
And a little salt.
Okay. We're gonna cook
this down for how long?
45 minutes, until it's nice
and thick and jammy.
And this is the foundation
to getting into
this turkey club?
-That's right.
-So now what do we have?
This is actually
a boneless turkey breast.
Cover it nicely
with some olive oil.
-Fresh herbs.
-Sage, rosemary, and thyme.
-Got it.
-Salt. Black pepper.
We're gonna massage it.
Turkey's happy, like, "Yeah."
All over.
And fresh flour and thyme.
That'll just melt
all into the flavor.
Okay. So we're gonna roast it
without any cover.
-How long?
-2 1/2 hours.
Let it cool.
And slice it for service?
-Yes.
-Fantastic.
What's our next step?
Crepe batter?
You know you're
full of crepe, right?
We're gonna start with water.
-Okay.
-Local farm-fresh eggs.
-Whoo! Look at that.
-That thing is live.
-Good thing you're over there.
-Things are gettin' gnarly.
-And we got some oil.
-Okay.
This is our house dry mix --
all-purpose flour,
whole wheat flour,
sugar, salt, and dry milk.
Watch out! That dust
is gonna hit you!
-Like a snow flurry.
-Gotta keep it funky fresh.
She means business, Rev.
She rocks.
And now we're ready
to make the crepe?
That's right.
Looks like turntables.
[ Imitating turn table ]
-I can get on 'em and rock.
-I could see it.
Watch this.
Wow.
You don't wanna spill
over the edges.
We see the color
comin' up here?
Yep.
We wanna get a nice
kind of sturdier crepe.
Okay.
We want something
that's a little bit crispy.
Sturdy crepe.
-Yeah. Sturdy crepe.
-So we're gonna have a --
So you're saying that's
a little bit thicker
than a regular crepe?
-Sturdier.
-Sturdier!
Don't add in, Rev!
I'm like,
we had to get him on that one.
-It was in stereo.
-All right.
Grab that sturdy crepe!
[ Laughs ]
The first ingredient --
our peach chutney.
I'm drowning in my own drool
right now, Rev.
Mozzarella cheese.
Our roast turkey breast.
Thick-cut applewood
smoked bacon.
Organic mixed greens.
The final ingredient
is our horseradish aioli.
I didn't see that
comin' at all.
Uh-huh.
Make sure
it gets nice and warm.
So here is our
Jammin' Turkey Club.
Mm, mm, mm.
That is a big lunch.
-Fantastic!
-I'm gonna get out of the way.
Okay, you should.
Uh, 'cause it's like,
it's getting ready to go down.
On three. One, two...
No, wait a second.
Is it one,
two, and then three?
No, it's one, two,
three, and here we go!
-Okay. 'Cause I...
-Here we go!
-Okay.
-Here we go! Here we go!
-Here we -- here we...
-Mm.
Wow.
The sweetness
of the chutney.
Cheese all pullin' up
in that piece.
The cheese comin' through that.
You get the creaminess of that.
The vessel that
you've got goin' on here
with this crepe,
it works great.
Nothing's overpowering
anything.
You haven't missed
a beat in this.
To be scratch-made,
homemade,
locally sourced
and to be that big,
that's real deal.
-Two turkey clubs?
-Thank you.
I love the spin
on a classic sandwich.
And turkey club's my favorite.
Rev, this is my buddy, Brandon.
He's the CEO
of the Tricky Triangle.
You ever been up
to Pocono Raceway?
Yeah.
What would your kids
think of this?
They'd lose their minds.
This right here,
it would blow anybody away.
One way to get me to eat
my fruits and vegetables, too.
I like this place
because they love what they do.
Everything's better
with bacon and jam!
And it transfers
right to the food.
What else are
the greatest hits here?
It's our 20-layer
orchard lemon cake.
We're goin' deep
when we get back.
We're hangin' out
at Jammin' Crepes.
It's all over our face.
It's just not right.
-We'll see you in a minute.
-Just wrong.
♪♪
What's up? We're here
in Princeton at Jammin' Crepes.
And we 'bout to do
this like Brutus
'cause we ain't new to this.
Can we go?
[ Laughs ]
-Was that good?
-It's fantastic.
So we did the turkey wrap.
So that's on the savory
side of things.
Yeah.
But you also do
a sweet side of things.
What is this we're gonna make?
The 20-layer orchard
lemon crepe cake.
I-I am not aware of anyone else
that sells something
as unique as this.
The good news is we've already
made the 20 layers of crepes.
Now we're just gonna make the --
the meringue-filled --
-We're gonna make the mousse.
-The mousse!
So we have cream cheese,
confectioner's sugar.
We incorporate
homemade applesauce.
-So that's kind of our jam.
-She went there on you.
She dropped it.
I'm gonna taste this.
Oh, yeah.
That's real deal right there.
-Wow.
-I'd like that on toast.
And then we have some really
nice fluffy whipped cream here.
So we're gonna
fold this together.
-Okay.
-Scoop that right in there.
And there we go.
These crepes seem
a little bit smaller
than the ones
that we used for the wrap.
This is a more classic
French batter that we use.
Okay.
And we cook
this on the stove
in a cast-iron crepe pan.
-So lighter and tender?
-You got it.
Okay. 20 layers.
We get our mousse on there.
Right. Gotta get
our mousse on.
-Layer two.
-Even layers. Even portions.
Thank you.
[ Laughs ]
Layer 20.
Lotta crepes.
What's up next?
'Cause we're just gonna eat that
if you don't --
We're gonna finish it
with a mountain of meringue
That's -- that's crazy.
I do not want one reference
to that meringue and my hair.
We kinda wanna
nice spiky finish.
Uh-oh.
Maybe I should step in
and show you how to do that.
That's why you said that.
I didn't know what you
were talkin' about
till she started
makin' your hairdo.
I didn't know that!
Now we're gonna torch it.
-It's beautiful.
-And there we go.
I don't know to eat it
or take a picture of it.
I'll take a selfie
with it like this.
Bam!
Out of bounds. Whoo.
We're gonna top it off
with a little lemon curd.
That tastes like wow.
So you get the great flavor
of the meringue, the curd.
But then what happens
is right in the middle,
all the substance is
that light,
fluffy French crepe.
And I'm lettin' you know,
there's 20 layers on there.
20-layer lemon crepe cake.
It's really light and fluffy.
And it tastes just
as delicious as it looks.
This is my manager,
Mike Lehman, here.
-This thing rocks.
-Watch out, Michael!
He's gonna try
to eat some of it.
The meringue is sweet.
Lemon is tart.
This is Anthony.
And he is the culinary director
for Knuckle Sandwich.
-This is unbelievable.
-I can see it's half gone.
Yeah, you know what?
It is what it is, bro.
Keep goin'.
[ Laughing ]
They definitely call themselves
Jammin' Crepes for a reason.
-Club up!
-I just love it.
I've seen some great creperies.
This is a little bit
different in quite a few ways.
Folks in this area
are lucky to have you.
-Next level.
-Well done.
-Can I get a fist?
They're like this.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Comin' up in Somersworth,
New Hampshire,
it's a scratch-made marathon!
It's delicious.
Startin' with bread
and hittin' everything
in between.
It's easy for it
to be extra great
when you're just
doing what you love.
[ Beatboxing ]
-FIERI: Yeah!
-I'm outie.
You know how they say that smell
really triggers the memory?
I mean, right now I'm trippin'
because I smell like
I'm in my hometown of Ferndale,
standing out here.
[ Inhales deeply ]
Oh, but I'm not!
I'm in Somersworth,
New Hampshire,
about 1/8 of a mile away
from the Maine border,
to check out a place
that totally reminds me of home.
This is Forty Five Market Street
Bakery and Cafe.
Spinach salad
and quiche of the day!
The food that they put out
is just love.
Grilled cheese?
Avocado and bacon?
Everything is always
super fresh, always.
Oh, it looks great.
FIERI: That's 'cause this
isn't Celeste Gingras
and Cheryl Arsenault's
first rodeo.
We've got 75 years
of restaurant
experience between us.
Cheryl and Celeste
are just amazing cooks.
Meatloaf sandwich is up!
It's wonderful turkey meatloaf.
The combination of the meat
and the bread,
the onions,
the sauce is incredible.
Turkey meatloaf,
I think it's awesome.
We use a lot of turkey
in my house.
-Let's get into it.
-The ground turkey.
Homemade bread crumbs.
Diced onion. Garlic.
Salt. Black pepper. Parsley.
Italian seasoning.
Got it.
And some fresh local eggs.
We just mix it up.
-Pat it in here.
-Yep.
And then into
the oven, what temp?
300, for 45, 50 minutes.
Are we doin' any glaze
or anything to it?
We're gonna make our
homemade barbecue sauce.
There we go, then.
A little olive oil
in the pot.
Chopped onions. Garlic.
-Brown sugar.
-Okay.
Worcestershire.
Isn't that a town
here close by?
-That's Worcester.
-Oh, Woostah!
Cider vinegar. Salt.
Ground red pepper.
Black pepper.
-Parsley.
-And boatloads of ketchup.
It's like, this much ketchup.
The official measuring system
here at Forty Fifth
Street Mah-ket!
-So now what do we have?
-Anadama bread.
-How do you get the name?
-Well, I didn't invent it.
They say it was invented
in New England, though.
-Molasses is in this?
-Yeah.
So we're just gonna
slice a couple slices
and toast 'em on the grill.
Okay. Mm, that's good.
Can people just buy
a loaf of it?
Absolutely!
We sell a lot of bread!
-Abso-loaf-ly!
-That could be our new tagline.
It's all yours.
You get the onions cookin' down.
I'm gonna make a little room
for the meatloaf.
Hit it with some
Provolone cheese,
a little barbecue sauce.
-Okay.
Hit it.
[ Whistles ] Look at that!
Besides them milking the cow
to make the Provolone,
all scratch-made.
-Yep.
Wow.
The sliced bread, it holds
together incredibly well.
And we're talkin' about a big
hot turkey meatloaf sandwich.
-It's sturdy as I get dirty.
-[ Laughs ]
-Huh? Yeah?
-Exactly.
The meatloaf itself
is not dried out, by any means.
You've got a nice little
panade there with
the breadcrumbs and the egg.
The barbecue sauce has got
a good sweetness to it.
It reminds me of a sandwich
that I would eat
when I was a kid.
Maybe it was something
my mom made or something.
Wow. That's great!
But I'm really havin'
a crazy flashback.
-It's delicious.
-Thank you.
Grilled meatloaf is up!
The meatloaf is so juicy.
That homemade barbecue sauce,
it gets me every time.
Their Anadama bread
is to die for.
FIERI:
Which isn't the only thing
they're scratch-bakin'
in this joint.
Cookies. Muffins.
They're known for their scones.
A lot of desserts.
The bread is always a star
in their sandwiches.
Haddock rolls up!
A delicious haddock sandwich.
Pan-fried in what we call
that Maine tradition.
And it's an excellent roll.
And it's obviously homemade.
So what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make the dough
for the snowflake roll.
Why do you call it
the snowflake roll?
You put the flour on the top.
And it kinda looks like snow.
Let's get into it!
All right. So we'll start
with some local honey.
Water.
Active dry yeast.
Got it.
High-gluten flour.
So canola oil. And some salt.
And then,
some all-purpose flour.
How long is this gonna go?
Oh, five minutes or so,
till it's smooth
and comes together in a ball.
-And then, I'll --
-So it speaks to you?
-Yeah.
-It is ready now.
How long's that
gonna take to proof?
-15, 20 minutes.
-Then we're gonna portion it?
Yep.
Ooh, you got
two hands goin' on it.
Yeah, you wanna
do it with me?
I can't get the left
hand to respond!
-I know, isn't it funny?
-The right hand, I'm good.
Yeah, you are.
It's the left
hand that's a hot mess.
That's okay!
I press 'em down
and put a little
more snow on the top.
Flour keeps it soft.
And how long does it go
in the oven for?
-About 18 minutes.
-Next up?
The dredge for the haddock.
-Fantastic.
-Cornmeal.
Hot paprika, Hungarian.
And black pepper.
Mix 'er up.
-Okay.
-Dip the haddock in the milk.
Cornmeal mix.
-We gonna get some oil goin'?
-And the haddock.
And this is fresh
haddock, local?
Yep. I love
the fish market.
Bakery but goes
to the fish mah-ket.
House pickled red onions.
Celeste's famous tartar sauce.
Celeste's famous
tartar sauce?
Yeah.
I like Celeste
just stays back there.
We talk to Celeste a lot.
We never see her.
She's just back there...
[ giggles ].
Green leaf lettuce.
Look at that, huh?
This has got fantastic flavor.
Thank you.
It's subtle.
It's not over the top.
Really good ingredients,
put together
in a really nice way.
I feel like I should be
eating this sitting on a dock,
having a nice big iced tea.
I wanted it to be
my New England experience
fried fish sandwich.
And it's every bit of that,
plus, plus
because
you're makin' the bread.
Delicious.
You can go anywhere
for a fish sandwich.
But people come here.
They cooked it to perfection.
Moist and tender.
Just the way it should be.
And the bread just makes it
all come together.
Pickled red onions
look great, Celeste.
Thanks.
They really, really love
to make delicious food.
It's easy for it
to be extra great
when you're just
doing what you love.
Right.
That's what you're
doin' right here.
Thank you.
It's awesome.
What a pleasure.
-Really appreciate it.
-Great time.
[ Boston accent ]
Forty Five Market Street.
-Good job.
-Mah-ket!
-Gotta get it right.
-Mah-ket.
Mah-ket on your calendar.
Up next,
in Louisville, Kentucky...
That's a great sandwich.
A pay-what-you-can spot...
There's a lot of
integrity in this.
...spreadin' the wealth
through their money menu.
-You did that 100% right.
-Thanks.
♪♪
I'm in the Portland
neighborhood
of Louisville, Kentucky,
to check out a joint
where I hear
that their community,
energy, attitude,
love, and appreciation,
well, is as great
as their food.
Remember, everyone's got
a seat at The Table.
I've got the peach salsa salad.
The Table is a very,
very special place.
Okra eggplant po' boy up!
This is not
a traditional restaurant.
FIERI: It's more of a mission,
led by John Howard
and Kathie and Larry Stoess
from the Church of the Promise.
We wanted to figure out
a relatable way
to love our neighbors.
FIERI: So they came up
with a non-profit concept
to serve others
through a community table.
Good quality food.
But you pay what you can.
And if you can't afford it,
you can always come back
and do dishes or --
or serve at the tables.
If you wanna leave a tip,
that's what you can
pay it forward.
This is my kinda church!
'Cause there's a lot
of integrity in this.
Starting with
Chef Laura Rountree,
who ditched fine dining
for her dream job.
I didn't really know
what I wanted to do
until somebody said,
"Here's a thing to do."
I was like,
"That's perfect."
You can't get any better food
in any of the higher-priced
restaurants.
Smoked pork up!
Today, I got the wonderful
smoked pork with the chow-chow.
Kind of like a pickled relish
type of thing?
It's awesome.
So we're gonna make
the barbecue spice rub.
-All right. Get after it.
-Paprika.
Cayenne pepper.
Chili powder.
That is some chili!
You're sure they're not coffee?
I know. It's really dark.
Cumin. Mustard powder.
Shout it out
when you know it!
BOTH: Granulated garlic!
[ Laughs ]
Brown sugar. Black pepper.
-And salt.
-All right.
So this is gonna
get applied to the butt.
Mm-hmm. We put it
in the cooler overnight.
How long is it gonna smoke,
at what temp?
9 hours at 160.
And then we do
7 hours at 250.
-You really goin' low and slow.
-Yeah.
-And then...
-We shred it.
-How are we gonna serve this?
-It goes on a Kaiser roll.
-Okay.
-With chow-chow...
Oh, we're gonna make some
chow-chow, right?
Mm-hmm.
So we have cabbage.
Yellow onion.
Mixed bell peppers.
That's gotta be local
garden bell peppers then
Mm-hmm.
-Green tomatoes.
-Okay.
A little bit of jalapeño.
And some salt.
Leave them in the cooler
overnight.
I dig it.
Okay. So the veggies
have been salted.
Look at all that liquid
that comes out of the veg
right there. Next up?
We have some mustard
seed and celery seed.
We're gonna toast
those a little bit.
-Oh, not in the toaster?
-Right. Exactly.
Yeah, that's hard
to get 'em out.
Apple cider vinegar.
-Water. Sugar.
-Okay.
Ginger powder. Mustard.
-That's red pepper flakes.
-Chili flake!
-Turmeric.
-Great color out of that!
Cinnamon.
And then we add our vegetables.
We reduce it. And it gets kinda
thick and syrupy.
-For how long?
-About an hour or two.
-Okay. Time to eat!
-Time to eat.
Put a nice scoop
of pork on there.
The chili mayo.
And we make this here, too.
-And our chow-chow.
-Is the bun local?
We have it cooked at
the culinary school here.
-Oh, really?
-Mm-hmm.
Mm. That's a great sandwich.
It's tender.
It's got good smoke.
That's the bark line
right there.
Mm-hmm.
Ooh, that's smoke's
comin' through.
The chow-chow plays
into it perfectly.
Bun is dynamite!
Culinary students
are doin' it right.
-It's a great sandwich.
-Oh, thanks!
-Nice job.
-Thank you.
More chow-chow, please.
One minute on the pork!
MAN: It's marvelous.
The pork is smoked
just perfectly.
Everything that she puts
on this sandwich
makes it an awesome sandwich.
You can see a ministry at work
and what it's doin' for people.
A lot of folks can't pay.
They're just told their
whole lives, in so many ways,
that they don't deserve
to eat like this.
But I think they do.
And they wanna have
an opportunity
to have somethin' like this.
-Right.
FIERI: Which is possible because
of the community volunteers
who help the small core staff
keep things goin'.
WOMAN: I was just here
two days ago working.
-I love it. What do you do?
-I love hosting.
Oh, I can see why.
That smile, right there.
I got chicken sandwich
and parm fries for you.
Today, I'm havin'
the smoked chicken sandwich.
It's served with a bacon jam
that is outrageously delicious.
What are we makin' next?
The brine that we put
on our chicken.
Okay, hit it!
All right. Water. Salt.
Sugar. Aromatics.
So some thyme and parsley?
A little peppercorn?
Mm-hmm. And the bay leaf.
Let that come to a simmer.
-Mm-hmm.
-Then cool it down.
Pour it on the chicken.
Let the chicken brine.
And then are we gonna
put a dry rub on that, also?
-Yes, dry rub.
-Same spice rub that we did?
-And then smoke it?
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
-And then shred it.
Great.
-What's up next?
-We're gonna make bacon jam.
-We start with...
-Bacon.
Bacon! Cook it down,
drain the fat.
Okay.
Pour a little bit of our reserve
bacon fat back in here.
Some yellow onion.
A bit of garlic.
Some coffee.
Didn't see that comin'.
Apple cider vinegar.
A bit of molasses.
Brown sugar.
Now the bacon back in.
Cook this a couple hours
till it gets nice and syrupy.
Break it down so it's nice
and jam-able.
-Spreadable, yeah.
-Here we go.
We're gonna start by putting
bacon jam on our top bun.
Red onion.
Some mixed greens.
Buttermilk ranch
that we make here.
-And then...
-The pulled chicken.
-Yes.
-And that's all she wrote.
Yep.
[ Mouth full ] We'll be back
after these messages.
[ Laughs ]
That is a dynamite sandwich.
The chicken's super flavorful,
not oversmoked, it's not dry,
and it doesn't
lack excitement.
Thanks.
So buttermilk ranch,
spot-on.
The sweetness
of the bacon jam.
No wonder you have so many
people wanna come volunteer!
Look at the...
You did that 100% right.
Thanks!
Smoked chicken up!
The chicken has
a nice smoky flavor.
It's delicious.
Who doesn't love
the bacon jam?
Those are my lines.
You could eat that
on a flip-flop.
Yeah.
Seek out The Table if
you're in the Louisville area.
You will definitely come back.
Such a neat program.
You know, I don't see
very many of these.
There's a great one in my town
of Santa Rosa called WOW.
I've seen so many positive
things happen through it.
And I watch what you're
doing here, takin' the time
and treating it as if you're
cookin' the presidential dinner.
To be treated respectfully
and lovingly does wonders
for people's attitudes
and self-esteem.
There's always room
at our table.
This is a place
you wanna visit.
So was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be lookin'
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"!
[ Whirring ]
[ Imitating Schwarzenegger ]
Yes, I'm workin' out right now,
doin' it one-handed.
[ Laughs ]
I did this
on "Terminator Crepe."
[ Laughing ]