Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
-Hi.
...we're cruising coast to coast
for some cosmopolitan comfort.
Wow, wow, wow, wow.
Like in a Minneapolis
hot dog spot...
I'll be here all week.
...going crazy
with the creations...
Oh, my gosh, dude.
And in Portsmouth...
[ Laughs ]
...a New Hampshire, New England,
new culinary twist.
Now, there's some
founding fathers
that are rolling over
right now.
Plus, real-deal Ethiopian
in Los Angeles...
Okay. All day.
...that is completely
out-of-bounds.
That's it!
I'm out!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
Believe it or not, I've been
duped at "Triple D"
a couple times before.
I didn't believe that
I could get ox-tails
at a bowling alley in Hawaii,
or that I could get great
Mexican food at a gas station.
So I'm here
I Minneapolis, Minnesota,
where I'm told there's a chef
that's scratch making
liver pâté,
making foie-gras gravy,
and hand-made sausages
all in a funky
little hot-dog joint.
This I got to check out.
Welcome to Prairie Dogs.
Got one Reuben-sausage
in the window.
Let's go.
-Oh, you can't beat it.
I got a Saucy Pig
for you here.
Really interesting twists
on basic Chicago dogs.
FIERI:
Which is rooted right into owner
Craig Johnson's background.
I went to culinary school
out in Portland, Oregon.
Before that, my first job
was at a country club,
slinging hot dogs.
Got two Micho's Sonoran Dogs.
Let's run these.
MAN: Chef Craig does great
things with food,
but his specialty
are the sausages.
A Jimmy Two Time Beef Combo.
Jimmy Two Times
is meat with meat.
It's like 16
different flavors.
Italian sausage Jimmy Two Times
combo with Italian beef.
I don't know what it meant,
but let's just start
with the sausage.
Pork what?
-Pork fat.
Add the chili flake.
Fresh garlic.
A little bit of sugar.
Kosher salt.
Toasted fennel.
Some dried sage.
-Big cracked rock pepper.
-Exactly.
So, you have
a grinder here in house?
I do. Now we're gonna add
the binder.
Milk powder that
has been bloomed in water.
And why not just milk?
I find that milk powder
does a better job.
It has more of a sticky
consistency, you know?
I'll listen to you.
And then case it off?
These are hog casings.
So, I link them
about five, six inches.
So, let them dry overnight.
Let all that flavor
come together.
Yep.
And then the next day,
I'll end up steaming them.
Now we're making
the Italian beef.
Walk me through it.
-We have black pepper.
Red chili flakes.
Kosher salt.
Powdered onion.
Granulated garlic.
Fresh oregano.
-Fresh oregano?
Then we're gonna put it
on the outside round.
Next, mirepoix.
And then the beef stock.
Then we're going in the oven.
Approximately five hours,
about 350.
Bring it out, let it cool,
slice it thin.
Now it's time
to put it together.
Throw the Two Time
in duck fat.
-Got it.
-In the meantime...
-...we got our Italian beef.
It's going in the jus,
get all that flavor.
[ Sizzles ]
Got a whole lot
of hot going on.
Then a Vietnamese-style
baguette.
We're all over the place.
[ Chuckles ]
All right. Beef, Jimmy
Two Time Italian sausage
on top of there.
Is that
a "Goodfellas" reference?
It is.
A little marinara.
A little marinara
going on that.
Pecorino Romano.
Put some house-made
jardiniere on there.
So, I'm supposed to
eat this or wear it?
That's proper stance.
Oh, my gosh, dude.
You've got to be
kidding me.
The sausage is fantastic.
The Italian beef
is dynamite.
The bread's no slouch.
The real surprise of the
whole thing is the jardiniere.
Wow, wow, wow, wow!
You crushed this.
-Awesome.
-Mmm!
-Order up.
-Looking good.
Nice, crisp sausage.
And a little bit of spice
on the top, which is nice.
I'd live here
if they'd let me.
Well, we'd be roommates.
We had Craig make our late-night
snack for our wedding,
and he was dressed
in a hot-dog costume.
And apparently,
a hot-dog costume
is something my crew
just can't resist.
[ Laughter ]
Could we get back
to work, please?
-What's coming up next?
-Two Prairie Dogs
and a Foietine.
FIERI:
Yeah, that's Foietine --
Craig's mashup of
foie gras and poutine.
It's really decadent.
Salty french fries
with the rich foie gravy,
and the cheese curds
top it off.
-Al right, let's get after it.
-We got some lamb neck.
-Lamb neck?!
-Salt and pepper.
So, seared neck bones,
mirepoix.
Toasted cumin, fennel,
and coriander.
One of my favorite bands.
-Bay leaves.
Rosemary. Garlic.
-Cinnamon.
-Tomato paste.
And red chili flake.
And a good half bottle
of some vino.
We got some chicken
stock here, too.
And then a little
bit of water.
Braise for about
four hours.
Then you pick through it
to get all the meat.
Now we're into
the foie-gras gravy.
We're gonna make our roux,
so we got bacon fat.
-There you go. Why not?
-Add our flour.
Our chicken stock.
Fresh thyme.
Allspice. Salt.
-And pepper.
-This comes to a boil.
If he keeps watching
it's never gonna boil.
Turn your back.
[ Whistling ]
All right.
Foie pieces go in.
-Dig it.
-Turn it up for heat.
Just what you find at
your average hot-dog joint.
And then blend that
all in there.
Make the hand-cut fries.
Mm!
That's a good fry.
Right there.
You don't have to
do anything to it.
Okay, go ahead.
Do something to it.
First, we're gonna add
the braised lamb neck.
A little bit
of chicken stock.
I'm just gonna continue
to sample these.
[ Chuckles ]
Next, cheese curds.
Does your mom know
you stole the plate?
[ Laughs ]
-I'll be here all week.
-Double-fried fries.
There's a few missing.
-No. Mnh-mnh.
Braised lamb neck and
our cheddar cheese curds.
Our foie gravy.
And then,
there's your vegetable.
That's gonna shrink the calories
right off of this one.
-What do you think?
-I think that if you told me
that I was having
some famous
Canadian-French Chef's
poutine spectacular...
...I wouldn't know
any different.
You got this really nice,
rich lamb,
complemented with
the cheese curds,
and then the velvet unctuousness
of the foie gravy.
I-I really probably think
this should be illegal.
[ Laughs ]
Why have ketchup when
you can have Foietine
with your french fries?
We don't spend a lot of time
in hot-dog joints
besides this one.
-This is crazy.
-It's fantastic.
We're that hot-dog
joint elevated.
No, what you are
is an elevated joint
that serves hot dogs.
-Thank you.
Watch out for this guy.
FIERI: Coming up...
Hi, welcome to
the Moxy Cooking Hour.
...creative culinary in
Portsmouth, New Hampshire...
I don't like it at all.
I love it.
...take a tradition
and turning it upside-down.
You did what?
So, have you ever heard
the word "moxie"?
Heard anybody use it?
Old-timers used to use it.
"That kid's got moxie."
Then there was the Moxie soda.
You know, to be fearless,
to have gusto.
Well, I'm here
in the downtown area
of Portsmouth,
New Hampshire,
to check out a restaurant
where the chef,
well, he's the living
definition of it.
This is Moxy.
-How we looking down there?
-Two minutes on stroganoff.
I get cravings
for Moxy all the time.
-Whoopies in the window.
-Tapas style.
Extremely creative.
Great for sharing
with your friends.
FIERI: All put out by chef
and owner Matt Louis,
who got his culinary courage
in big-league kitchens
all across the country.
Lacquered pork belly bites.
FIERI: Then he returned
to his home state
with the attitude behind
his restaurant's name.
This is a little bit
aggressive for Portsmouth.
It's a little bit
unique approach.
Kind of a funky spin
on New England cuisine.
New England Dinner 2.0.
The New England Dinner
2.0 is corn beef,
pickled vegetables, kind of wrap
it like lettuce wrap.
You're taking traditional
New England brisket
and turning it
into a lettuce cup?
-Yes, Chef.
-Nice!
The first part is
to build the brine
for the corn beef brisket.
Here's our water.
Salt.
Sugar.
Garlic cloves.
Little bit of curing salt.
And you need that
for the color.
So, then, all
the pickling spices --
cinnamon stick,
peppercorn, bay leaf...
Beautiful.
...brown ginger,
-Cardamom...
...yellow mustard seeds,
chili flakes,
clove,
juniper, coriander.
Once it dissolves,
we're good to cool it down.
Fantastic.
All right.
Any particular brisket
you're using?
We use beef brisket.
As opposed to
the chicken brisket.
It's not as popular
as it used to be.
It really has fallen
out of favor lately.
Fallen out of flavor!
Put it in a non-reactive
container.
Don't give me all the big,
important words.
So, we got
a plastic bucket here
with the beef brisket.
We're gonna dump
our cooled brine over the top.
[ Laughs ]
With a bag of frozen water --
ice, as you say --
we're gonna weight it down
with a weight on top.
-Oh!
-So, this brisket's been
in a brine
for 10 days here.
Fill it up with water.
Hit this liquid
as it cooks
with a little bit more
of the pickling spice.
We'll put it to
a gentle simmer for 3.5 hours,
keep a nice
little bubble going on.
Going on.
So, next up, we're gonna
make the maple mustard
we're gonna serve with it
as kind of the dipping sauce.
Brisket, mustard --
they go together
like tuna fish
and peanut butter.
It might be a stretch,
but I can work with that.
We'll start
with egg yolks.
We'll add a little bit
of lemon juice.
I have two mustards here.
This is called White Lightning,
little bit spicier.
And this is called Old World,
little bit sweeter.
Maple syrup.
Little tip for the home cook --
a nice, wet towel
under the mixing bowl
frees up the second hand.
[ Laughs ]
Hi, welcome to
the Moxy Cooking Hour.
Add the oil slowly
into the egg yolk to form
a nice creamy mixture.
-Luxurious.
-And add a little bit of salt.
Little bit of pepper
and then we'll give it a taste.
I get nice maple.
I definitely could
go more mustard.
Chef, I'm thinking
a shot of lemon juice, too.
And I could also
do a touch of salt.
See, here's what's
beautiful about this.
You're not sticking to strict
recipe-ing guidelines.
-Totally.
-Okay.
Now we're getting
ready for service.
We have the brisket.
We like to trim off
some of that excess fat --
slice it,
reheat it in the original
cooking liquid.
-Napa cabbage.
-Here's the maple mustard,
some crispy potato sticks.
Brisket, root vegetables,
carrots, onions, potatoes.
2.0 aspect --
we pickle the carrots to make it
a little bit fresher,
a little more modern.
Top it with a little
bit of parsley,
and that's the New England
Boiled Dinner 2.0.
Now, there's
some founding fathers
that are rolling over
right now.
"You did what?!"
The build-your-own
sharing style sticks
with our tapas
mentality here.
-I didn't here anything
you said.
-I'm sorry.
What was that?
-Who?
[ Grunts ]
Thank you.
Awesome crunch coming
from the cabbage.
Napa's definitely
the way to go.
The brisket --
outstanding texture to it,
pick up a lot of
the pickling spice.
Love the fat
that's in it.
One of my favorite parts
is the maple inside of the
aioli,
the mustard, whatever
you want to call it.
That, to me, adds that
little touch of sweetness,
which you really need.
You just get just enough
of that awesome New England
corn beef traditional dinner.
Awesome job.
-I'm glad you like it.
-I don't like it at all.
I love it.
Wow!
I'll be asleep
in the basement.
MAN: Corn beef
is perfectly salty.
It's got a great texture.
-It's surprising.
It's different and
it's really delicious.
In the world of "Triple D"
we have "Triple D" royalty.
People who have been on the show
and have just exploded.
Here we have two
of my favorite chefs,
Chef Carl. Chef Bri.
Chef Carl now, has also been
one of the fantastic champions
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
He's also a judge for us.
And then they have
fantastic taste testers,
Michelle and Robert.
What do you think, buddy?
-It's amazing.
I like all the toppings because
I love putting everything
together when I eat.
I love the fact that I'm eating
it with moon pies.
-Which goes hand-in-hand.
-It does.
WOMAN:
Every time I come in here,
I'm eating something
that I've never tried before.
I think Matt is a wizard.
This is the part where
I'm supposed to leave.
I got to jump in the Camaro,
take off to the next joint.
But I'm not going anywhere
and neither are you.
So stick around.
We'll come back
to Portsmouth, New Hampshire.
Hanging out at the Moxy.
Well, the chef's gonna
do some more magic.
See you in a bit.
I still want to go lay down
in the basement.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're hanging out
in Portsmouth, New Hampshire.
I'm glad to see that you have
the Moxy to stick around.
Huh? How'd I use that?
-That was good.
Funky, little
tapas joint,
where the chef is taking
New England classics
and kind of doing
his own little spin.
Tons of respect
for the farm-to-table attitude.
MAN: The chef knows
the local farmers,
he knows their products --
You're tasting the area.
I saw there's a big map
with a bunch of flags in it,
and those are all the farms
that you buy from?
A lot of the farms we use,
as well as the plaques
on the wall behind the bar.
Knowing how fresh it is just
makes it that much better.
Goat stroganoff
going to Table 2.
Had the goat stroganoff.
It's very delicious.
Goat stroganoff,
'cause you hear it every day.
We get whole goats right down
the street from Riverslea Farm.
So, to start this off,
we're going to braise pieces
of the goat leg,
season the meat --
salt, pepper.
Into the oil,
sear this on all sides.
We're going to
add our mirepoix.
We've got our
aromatics here,
our thyme, fresh bay,
garlic, cloves, peppercorns.
-Got it.
Then we've got
our goat stock
that we made from
the bones of the goat.
You are just
one resourceful machine.
We're going to bring this up,
turn it down,
do a gentle simmer,
till about 3 hours.
Now we have
the shreddable goat.
We just pull it into
this extra pan over here.
Those are like, you got enough
texture on the outside of it
from the sear, you didn't
overcook it to the point
where it's just shreddy,
dusty goat.
We got some good fat.
Next up?
-We're going to take the jus,
and we're going to strain it
right over that,
keeps it even moister
than it is right now.
-Did you say "even moister"?
-Even moister.
Is that a town close
to Portsmouth?
Oh, you have Gloucester
and then Even Moister.
I heard Flavortown
was in the middle
of there somewhere.
-You've got it right.
We're going to saute
fingerling potatoes, carrots,
a little fresh, cracked pepper,
going to add
the sour cream into the goat.
And now we're
ready to plate.
Plate this dish.
The potatoes and the carrots
to make a little nest,
the the goat
stroganoff itself.
-So, it's like a goat moat.
-Crispy potato, fresh dill.
You gotta have the dill.
And here's
our goat stroganoff.
Outrageous.
The sour cream, goat,
dill combo might be
one of the best ways
I've ever had goat.
It is nuts, man.
You get that little tang
coming from the sour cream,
you get the freshness
of the dill.
The potato and the carrots
cooked perfectly.
I think of eat it and fall
asleep on the couch
or at the bus stop.
Love it.
Outstanding.
-Goat stroganoff.
Creamy, exceptionally tender,
crunchy and savory
and delicious.
The way Matt is,
the way the food is,
it's got moxie.
The name fits, doesn't it?
Moxy's always your sure bet.
This is an experience
you can't miss.
I mean, you're an hour
from Boston?
-Yeah.
-They're gonna build
a high-speed train
from Boston straight here.
You think they'll
let me drive it?
You can always wish.
FIERI:
Up next, a mother/daughter
duo in Los Angeles...
You guys are like
culinary ambassadors.
...putting their family Dutch
on Ethiopian favorites.
There's something
going on in this kitchen
that I'm not getting
brought into.
That was the touch.
Make sure that one goes.
Don't cut that one out.
So, I'm here in Los Angeles,
California,
and I'll tell you something
funny about "Triple D."
I go to a place
that I've been before,
and I find another "Triple D"
joint right next door.
Wait a second. That rhymed.
Anyhow, I'm at
the Mercado La Paloma
to check out Azla,
Ethiopian Vegan.
WOMAN:
You want the gomen?
MAN:
Man, this stuff is amazing.
It is the most
authentic Ethiopian food
you're every going to get.
-Can I get the tofu tips?
WOMAN #2:
Everything here is vegan,
but that doesn't take away
from the flavor at all.
It's really good.
FIERI: And it's put out
by a mother/daughter team --
Azla and Nesanet Abegaze.
who are serving up food
from the homeland
with their own family flavor.
-Enjoy your meal.
-Azla has six kids.
We all became vegetarian
about 15 years ago.
She had to learn to start
cooking things
a little differently.
-Are most Ethiopians vegetarian?
-No.
90% of our customers
are not vegetarian.
You guys are like
culinary ambassadors.
FIERI:
In an Ethiopian cuisine,
it all starts out
with the edible flatware.
Injera is the Ethiopian
form of bread.
...that you use
to pick up your food.
WOMAN: We're going to make
our injera batter.
So, this is the teff grain.
It's ground up,
quinoa flour, and then water?
-A little at a time.
Hi.
I'm making bread.
-This is too high.
-Just do it on the floor.
Mom does it by hand,
She actually says her prayer
as she's making it.
The prayer is, "Can someone
please get me a mixer?"
Right? [ Laughs ]
Here, Mommy.
-Can we at least put it there?
After she's done with this,
we'll ferment it for three days.
So, water will
rise to the top.
-Right.
-Skim off the top
to appropriate consistency.
So, we're talking,
like, pancake batter.
Yep. Now we're going
to make our Misir Wot.
Mister without the "T."
Okay.
Which is our spicy
red lentils.
-So, the onions.
-Tomato.
Why don't we put
the oil in first?
-We have to cook them more.
-Okay.
We'll cook the oil
for about, maybe, 10 minutes.
And the berbere?
That's the spices.
All of it?
-Yeah. Go crazy.
"Go crazy."
Add water, and then,
when the water comes to a boil,
that's when you
add the lentils.
How long's that
going to cook down?
About, what?
An hour, two hours, Mom?
-Yeah.
-So, I asked the question,
and she asked you
in English,
and you respond
to me in English.
I'm not allowed to talk
directly to the chef?
[ Laughs ]
Okay, now we're
making the injera.
-Yep.
-Whoa.
That is only crazy spatula.
Holy tortilla, Batman.
It feels like
a crepe meets a tortilla.
It's spongy.
Huh.
Okay, so the lentils are done.
A little nutmeg
and salt in those.
This is a curry potatoes,
carrots and cabbage.
Okay.
So, dip in like that?
Yeah.
Okay.
All day.
It's fantastic.
This is lighter
than a tortilla.
But there's a ton of flavor
in that, and it's spicy.
Yep. [ Laughs ]
Yeah.
It's not overly spicy.
You're just getting a nice,
warm heat throughout.
Enormous depth of flavor.
There's only one question
that's coming to my mind.
It's, "Where's this
been all my life?"
I don't get blown away
very often.
It's outstanding.
-I'll get the misir wot.
It has a little bit of punch.
Delicious to eat with injera.
The spice is off the chain.
FIERI: Because the components
are as legit as it gets.
Azla goes back to Ethiopia
and gets it
and brings it back here.
So you do your own blending
to make your berbere?
-Yes.
-You make your own style.
Berbere just
heightens the flavor.
It heightens the intensity
of the dish.
It gives it the extra kick
that I really like.
This is a place you can
easily get addicted to.
You have all these colorful
options to choose from.
FIERI: Which includes one of
their family favorites.
We're going to make churro,
churro wot in
our special clay pot.
Churro is delicious,
almost like a stew consistency.
Growing up, whenever it would
rain, my mom would make this.
On a cold day, there's nothing
better than hot churro.
-Get a little churro.
-Yep. You eat it with injera.
I eat everything
with injera now.
Onions and the tomato.
That's a lot of oil.
But now we're ready
for the water.
So it'll come to a boil.
-Now we drop in the flour.
So, my mom just got
back from Ethiopia,
so these are a few
of the beans
that go into making
the churro flour.
The garbanzo
that's roasted.
That's a small garbanzo.
And what is this?
This is like a type of pea,
and then they grind it up
with some other spices,
and that's how you
get the churro flour.
-Next?
-Now it's thickened up
and we're ready
for our minced garlic,
salt and then jalapeño.
You really get after it
with the jalapeño
in this Ethiopian food.
Okay, it cooks for 40 minutes,
and then we serve
that alongside with the...
-The gomen.
-The gomen is, like,
an interesting twist
on collard greens,
because it's kale
and it's got, like,
that Ethiopian kick to it.
When it comes
to collards or kale,
I go out of my mind.
So I gotta go there first.
There's something going
on in this kitchen
that I'm not getting
brought into.
There's no animal fat
in that at all.
Our customers
question us all the time.
You got a ham hock in there?
[ Laughs ]
Those are lights-out greens.
This...
Burrito time.
Oh, yeah! It's creamy,
and I love how much garlic
gets put into play.
Oh, that is so good.
When you love
what are you doing
the food is going
to taste good.
The food tastes
better than good.
Yeah.
Boy, it's interesting --
the more I love her food,
the more her English
gets better.
[ Laughter ]
-The churro.
-Churro, okay.
MAN: The churro is very deep,
rich flavor.
The spices really just hit it.
I've been to a lot
of vegetarian restaurants,
but, without question,
this is one of the best
I've ever seen.
MAN: The best Ethiopian food
that's not in Ethiopia,
you gotta come to Azla.
I mean, lights out, fantastic.
Do you high-five?
Can you break it down?
[ Laughter ]
That's it!
I'm out!
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
Where are you from?
That's what you get for reaching
over and taking my cornbread,
is I'm going to ask you
a question right
when your mouth's full.
[ Laughs ]