Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That ain't no
Christmas cookie.
That's right,
today is more like sausage.
Welcome
to Carnivore Hour.
Seafood.
Mm! Fantastic.
And even a little shawarma.
That is shawarma 101.
Like at a money Miami spot,
cooking up real-deal Haitian.
A little island paradise.
An international journey,
nestled right in New Hampshire.
This is
a rocking sandwich.
And a crazy family joint
in Minneapolis.
I think we
might be cousins.
Cooking up pizza
with pizzazz.
You're a gangster.
-What up?
Dawg.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
Now, we get recommendations
for "Triple D" joints
from a lot of people,
but in particular,
when your crew that shoots
"Triple D" --
Hold on.
This crew right here,
when they tell you
that you gotta come
check out a pizza joint
that's right down the street
from their house,
well, you know I'm there.
This is Red Wagon Pizza.
[ Laughs ]
Báhn mí pizza.
It's a different kind
of pizza joint.
So neighborhood, so right.
Grabbing a Popeye.
You kind of feel like
you're inserting yourself
in someone's
family tradition.
FIERI:
Because you kinda are,
one that Peter Campbell's
grandparents started long ago.
That's your grandfather.
That's my nana
in the middle
and my mom on the far left
in the late '40s.
Pop pop would do these pizza
parties in his basement.
The community
would come out.
And Peter picked up
where his grandpa left off
when he opened the doors
here in 2014.
We forge pizzas.
Whoo-oo!
I don't know what he's on.
-30 seconds on a Red Wagon!
The Red Wagon pizza
is the best pizza.
WOMAN: The peppers, the spice,
the sausage, cheese.
Just the most tasty piece
of pizza I've ever encountered.
All right, Pete,
let's make the magic dough.
Cold water.
Then we take day-old dough.
-The mother.
Tear apart the dough
in the water
and get the water
nice and milky.
Dry active yeast.
The flour
is a heritage meat.
[ Scat singing ]
We'll hit this on 1.
We'll scrape the bowl
after 2.5 minutes,
run it again for
2.5 minutes,
then we'll throw in salt,
cover it,
let it rest for 30.
Run the mixer for about
nother 5 minutes.
Grab a hunk of dough,
just make sure
that it'll stretch
and it's nice and thin.
You guys understand
what's happening here?
You go and stretch it
and it splits open,
then it hasn't built
the gluten.
It has to be mixed
a little bit more.
Bring it out, let it rest
for 24 hours, portion it.
Welcome to Carnivore Hour.
♪♪
I'm Guy and this is...
-Pedro.
Now, we're into
making the sausage.
Pork butt,
it's all cubed up.
Bacon, soppressata.
We have garlic,
onion, fennel powder.
Salt. Ground pepper.
-But no henway?
I don't know. What's
a henway? [hen weigh]
About 2 or 3 pounds.
-[Chicken clucks]
[ Woman cackles ]
I think we might be cousins.
We're gonna let it cure
overnight in a cooler.
And then, in the morning,
we grind it,
put it on sheet trays,
and cook it off
in the oven.
All the pies are 14 inches.
Housemade sauce.
A blend of half-mozzarella
and half-Provolone.
Let me bring in
the real pro.
Buck, come on in here
for a second.
This is Buck,
the older brother.
Pete, why don't we just have you
step out for a little bit?
-Yeah. I don't know.
-It was nice having you
on the show.
-I'm wondering if we shouldn't
start over.
-[Cackles]
He just left the building.
Come on over, Pete.
-[Laughs]
It's a little oblong.
We can work on your
technique a little bit.
Thank you, Buck.
We liked having you.
All right.
-Ha ha!
House sausage,
banana peppers.
Then we take the soppressata,
we slice it in a ribbon.
90 seconds, comes out,
we'll slice it up.
What do we throw in here?
Buzzed-up,
crushed red pepper.
This is a housemade
garlic salt,
fig-infused balsamic.
There you go, Red Wagon Pizza.
-Typically, they're round.
[ Laughter ]
It's dynamite.
Everything you're doing
in the pizza is balanced.
Freshmade sausage.
You've got handmade dough.
You've got homemade sauce.
You got a nice
little acid bite in there
coming from
the banana pepper.
A little touch
of the chili flake.
It's an artisan pizza, man.
Everybody at home
right now is going, "Oh,
I want a bite of that pizza,"
'cause it's the real deal.
Fantastic.
-Thank you.
Mm.
You can tell the care
that goes into it
when you take
that first bite.
It has some sweet.
It has some spice.
It has a little kick.
I have Red Wagon socks.
-[Woman laughs]
Check it. What up?!
[whispering] Is Pete really
as crazy as he sounds?
He's pretty crazy.
It's hard to taper
back the pizzazz.
I got a lotta
pizzazz in me.
He burns a lotta octane,
doesn't he?
[laughing] Yes.
He has all the right
energy about him.
MAN: Yeah.
-He wants it to be
family-oriented.
He wants it to be scratchmade.
Anything you order
is gonna be great.
Two tortellinis walking
to the window.
The tortellini looks like
it should be
a 4-star restaurant.
Homemade pasta.
They make the ricotta.
Now, we're gonna
make the ricotta?
Yeah.
2 gallons whole milk.
Heavy cream.
Lemon juice.
-Apple cider vinegar
and we're gonna give it
a little heat.
Low heat.
We're gonna separate
the curd from the whey.
You'll run it
through the cheesecloth.
Hang it in
the cooler overnight.
You're going for
a really dry ricotta.
Right.
Now, we're gonna make
the spinach purée.
Start with ice.
Blanched spinach.
Sautéed garlic, onion,
salt, pepper,
and a wee bit o' oil.
That, I like.
Boom.
That, now, mixed with ricotta,
into the piping bag.
You also make the pasta?
-Oh, yeah.
-You're killing me.
This is not
a one-bite tortellini.
All right, so you ready
for this, homie?
See it, homes.
-So we have the spinach ricotta.
Put the top,
drop the thumbs,
knead it forward
so you get the scoop,
and then boom.
You're a gangster.
-What up?
Dawg.
[Laughter]
So we're gonna drop the
tortellinis that we just made.
We're gonna reduce
some white wine
and a cheesy Béchamel.
Now add the ham.
Fresh peas.
-Tortellini.
We're gonna reduce this
down a little bit more.
Delicately dropped.
A little oil.
Our gremolata.
What's in the gremolata?
-Parmesan,
red-pepper flake,
and oregano.
Beautiful-looking plate.
Nice and pillowy.
It's fantastic.
You play at full speed.
You only have a 10,
like the knob got broken at 10.
Outstanding.
Fabulous.
I would not expect
a tortellini that good
to be found
at a pizza place.
It's the place you have to go.
You just have to try it.
FIERI: Phenomenal.
It comes from
a great foundation.
It's like a storybook.
-Thank you.
I love it.
Coming up...
an eclectic spot
in Portsmouth, New Hampshire.
I'm trusting you
on this.
Putting their spin on
round-the-world street food.
Good luck wrapping
that up, there, homes.
Good luck eating it.
3 minutes, salt,
[Stammering]
Close. We're not
gonna hire you,
but it's 2.5 minutes.
[Laughter]
[ Beep ]
♪♪
So, when you're cruising
up the 95
between Boston
and Portland, Maine,
and you get off
on the first exit,
for Portsmouth, New Hampshire,
well, you'll find yourself
at a place that'll have
your head spinning.
Am I in Venice Beach?
Am I in Soho?
No, you're at a funky
little joint called Street 360.
♪♪
Steamed dumpling.
Thai rib.
Unbelievable.
Everything is unique.
What did I step into?
An amazingly
eclectic restaurant.
Mexicali, in the window.
The concept is brilliant.
It's a restaurant
of street food
from around the world.
And the culinary trip
going on here comes
from husband-and-wife team
Josh Lanahan
and Michelle Lozuaway,
who travel the globe
for their inspiration.
They've been everywhere
and whatever they like,
they brought it here.
So it is like a food lesson
from all over the world.
The seafood samita.
Samita's a Mexican sandwich
from Pueblo, Mexico.
But, here, it's getting
a seafood spin.
I've never had seafood
like this, in a burger.
Hit it.
-We've got fresh local pollock,
shallots, shrimps,
and scallops
that we're gonna grind.
-Very nice.
We add some diced
sea scallops.
Okay, so a little
more texture in there.
Yeah. Shrimp.
Then with some eggs
from my own chickens.
These are our --
-How many chickens do you have?
We have 17. We had
100, at one point,
but, that was
way too many.
And then the panko.
-Yep.
Next step, we add our spices.
-Okay.
Kosher salt, fresh-ground
black pepper, dried thyme,
a little cayenne pepper,
and then mix it up.
Now form it into molds.
-Right.
Patty these all out,
pop 'em right
in the freezer.
Out of the freezer, bread 'em,
flour, egg wash, panko?
Yep, standard
breading procedure.
Drop to the fryer.
Dig it.
What are we into now?
-Chipotle mayonnaise.
-All right, hit it.
We got roasted
red peppers,
Spanish onions,
chipotles in Adobo.
A little bit of ketchup,
fresh garlic,
kosher salt,
and fresh cilantro.
You have a good flow,
my friend.
So, now, we put our
mayonnaise in a bowl.
That's a lotta food lube.
-That's good on everything.
-Fold that in.
-Whisk it together,
let it sit
for an hour or so.
Delicious.
-Here's our
seafood samita patty.
We're serving it on
a toasted sesame-seed bun.
And we take a slice of blanco
cheese on the griddle,
our chipotle mayonnaise,
plenty of it, and then...
Cilantro, like a salad.
These are our pickled red
onions that we make here.
And then, because
it doesn't have enough,
some fatty avocado.
There you go.
Nice wrapup, son.
The cheese is gangster, dude.
-Right?
But cheese and seafood?
I'm trusting you on this.
♪♪
This is a rocking sandwich.
I mean, really good.
You really concentrated
on texture.
You get the scallop in there,
and you get those big chunks
of the shrimp in there.
And then you accentuate with
the different layers of flavor.
With the creaminess
of the avocado
and the little bit of the bite
that you're getting
from the chipotle mayo.
And then, the big, herbaceous
note of tons of cilantro.
Really nice toasted bun,
creaminess of the cheese.
-It works.
-Dynamite.
Order up:
seafood samita.
It's absolutely delicious.
I don't know how to describe
the fried cheese.
It's so good.
Street is definitely
a community
where everyone can come
and share a delicious meal.
It's eclectic.
It's fun.
It's certainly
a different environment.
It's got its own thing,
especially in this area.
WOMAN: Portsmouth is a beautiful
little sea town.
Always has tourists,
but we're just
a little bit
off the beaten path.
This town does
a lot of seafood,
so having these kind of
nontraditional comfort
foods is a nice break.
I got a lamb shawarma, side
curry fries, in the window.
The lamb shawarma is great.
-So much flavor.
It's definitely
a little bit messy,
but it's worth it.
Lamb shawarma.
Our version.
Unfortunately, we don't
have a vertical spit,
so we have to roast
our lamb.
Okay.
-We're gonna make our spice rub.
Fresh-ground black pepper,
ground cinnamon,
little bit of turmeric,
ground clove,
kosher salt, paprika,
fresh bread,
granulated garlic,
ground cumin,
ground coriander.
So all the key spices.
We're gonna rub liberally.
Feel the burn.
We're gonna put
sliced onions
and whole garlic
as a bed.
Wrap it in the oven.
-4 hours.
-At?
-325.
Thing's gonna shred,
for sure.
All right, brother,
tzatziki time.
Tzatziki.
We got our really thick,
strained, beautiful,
Greek yogurt.
You get strange Greek yogurt.
-Yeah. It's very strange.
Coming from you,
that's gotta be strange.
-[chuckle] European cucumber.
-Okay.
Fresh mint, fresh dill,
white pepper;
kosher salt, again;
cayenne;
a little bit of milk.
Because our yogurt's
so thick,
need a little bit
of thinning.
And fresh lemon juice.
That's gonna be
a ton of flavor.
Take our lamb
out of the oven.
Mix all those onions
and the garlic in
with the meat.
-Now to the flat top.
Put a little bit of butter
on our Greek-style pita.
Nice-looking pita.
Now, we're gonna
build the sandwich.
So we got our lamb, right?
-Look at that.
A little sliced onion.
Tomato.
Our tzatziki, and then
shredded lettuce.
Good luck wrapping
that up there, homes.
I know it.
Good look eating it.
Dude!
We have a side
of our curry fries here.
This is a curry
mayonnaise.
Then we have a salady
curry ketchup, as well.
I always like to cleanse
my palate with a nice fry.
All right.
♪♪
If you've never had
lamb shawarma,
this is probably the best
interpretation I've seen,
without going to
a vertical spit.
The crunch and the texture
that it's developed.
I mean, that is shawarma 101.
The tzatziki, superflavorful,
with the right amount of dill.
A great pita
that's going with it.
I mean, a fantastic pita.
But the real kicker here
is what you've done
with the lamb.
When you throw that lamb
on that flat top
and it's screaming hot,
well, you got 'em.
Lamb shawarma
with curry fries.
The lamb's always
cooked to perfection.
The sauce is
out of this world.
International passport
to deliciousness.
International -- that is
a mic drop, you know this.
The best food that you could
possibly get in Portsmouth.
A lot of people would like
to have an eclectic menu,
but when you have
an eclectic menu,
you really have to be
able to deliver,
and you nailed it.
Watch out for this guy.
Up next...a legit
Haitian chef in Miami.
You're really
getting after it.
Spicing up specialties
from his homeland.
I love this.
Exactly what I wanted.
Making seafood samitas.
[ Clanking ]
Don't worry, I got this.
[Clanking]
[ Beep ]
♪♪
You know what we
don't see enough of?
Haitian restaurants.
I have this Haitian buddy.
He's taken me to these
outrageous restaurants in Miami,
but here I am in North Miami.
Where am I gonna
get the Haitian food?
Now, don't judge, 'cause I know
I'm in a strip mall,
but I hear the place is legit.
This is Ivan's Cookhouse.
♪♪
Salmon, let's go.
My favorite restaurant
in the whole city.
Shrimp mofongo pickup
at the windows.
Chef Ivan is amazing.
Pick up an Island Coconut
Curry Chicken, guys.
I'm originally from Haiti
and I feel like
I'm still at home
when I'm here.
FIERI: That's 'cause,
since 2015,
owner and "Chopped" champion
Ivan Dorvil --
-Thank you.
-Has been dishing out
the culinary cornucopia
he grew up with.
The history of Haiti.
You got French.
You got Spanish.
You got Indian.
You got African.
You got all those
spice combined.
He plans and mixes
and it's an amazing fusion.
Pick up a griot
and a black rice, guys.
Griot is fried pork.
It's a traditional
Haitian food.
And the black rice, back
home, we call it djon djon.
It is absolutely delicious.
Griot, that's like a key
in Haitian food.
In Haitian food,
it is a key.
Every household,
you know about griot.
Okay. So we have pork shoulder.
-Pork shoulder.
You're really getting
after it.
Got some kosher salt.
Do you pour it
from the heavens?
That's exactly.
Some sour orange.
And white vinegar.
Now we're gonna
just wash it
and then we marinate it.
-Hit it.
First, some celery,
a bunch of parsley in there.
-Okay.
-Next, Scotch bonnet.
-How many are you gonna put
in there?
-Two or three.
-Okay.
-Some fresh thyme.
We do some garlic.
-Okay.
Some chicken bouillon
and some sour orange.
Sour orange.
♪♪
Magic show.
-That's it.
Throw it right back
to the meat.
We're gonna dive
into it.
You really did change
the whole show.
We're gonna let that marinate.
And after that, we just
put it right in the pan,
sear it a little bit,
-Okay.
and then we put water,
let it boil.
And then, once it's done,
what's gonna happen?
We're gonna
flash fry it.
Flash fry.
What are we making now?
Some black rice. First,
some dried mushroom.
That's what we call
djon djon in Creole.
Djon djon.
-And I just get some hot water
and boil it up
about 5 minutes,
let it sit there,
and that's exactly
why you got that.
-So that's the steeping liquid
from the djon djon.
-From djon djon, exactly.
Both of those
are gonna go in there?
Yes. That's how
we make the rice.
Got it.
-So, first, some olive oil.
We're gonna add
some herbs here.
It looks like garlic.
It looks like parsley.
-Garlic, parsley.
-It looks like celery.
-That's exactly right.
-All right. Next.
Lima bean.
Chicken bouillon.
Some rice.
We'll toast the rice off
and then we'll hit
the djon djon
steeping liquid.
-Put the
-Thyme and the parsley.
thyme and the parsley.
And, last...
Oh, yeah.
Are those cloves jammed
into a Scotch bonnet?
That's exactly right.
So the Scotch bonnet's
not enough?
We're gonna jam
some cloves in it.
That's it, so the flavor,
it could infuse the rice.
I like it.
Let it come to a boil.
Lower the heat a little
bit and cover it up
and then that's it.
-Okay, Chef.
We're gonna plate
the griot.
Got nice, brown,
soft pork.
Got some pikliz.
-Some pikliz?
Haitian cabbage,
almost like kimchi.
[ Whistles ]
[Laughter]
-That's -- Yeah.
That's the fiery, yes.
That ain't no
Christmas cookie.
And you got two
plantain here
and then, top it off
with sautéed onion.
Here's my black rice.
-Voilà.
♪♪
Mmm!
That works.
The pork's
super-supertender.
A little texture
on the outside.
You pick up a little bit
of that vinegar.
You pick a little
sour orange.
Rice is tender. I like the
little mushroom hint in there.
That little bit of earthiness
that comes from
the steeping liquid.
A little bit
of that spicy pikliz.
♪♪
Mmm! I love this.
Exactly what I wanted.
There you go.
The meat's perfect.
The black rice has brought me
to another place right now.
You want to eat more.
It's like it's asking you
to come back for more.
When you have real-deal,
legit, Haitian food
for the first time,
with a Haitian buddy,
well, you can't forget him.
This is my buddy Patrick.
Now, Patrick also happens to be
the dude that makes my shirts.
He owns this company
called Bagose.
So, being that he knows
great Haitian food,
how legit is this?
-It's great.
They are doing it
extremely right.
How do you describe
really good Haitian food?
The spices, they have to be
all over the food.
You see it, you smell it.
I'm talking to you here.
I want to stop talking.
I want to eat it.
Go ahead. I mean, get it
all over your nice shirt.
[ Laughs ]
Pick up a griot
and snapper.
That red snapper
is amazing.
Red snapper,
when you say Haitian food,
this is like a staple.
-Exactly.
-Okay.
-That's it right there.
♪♪
Mm.
It's delicious.
You get the garlic,
a little salt and pepper.
Fresh, local snapper.
You're almost eating
the entire fish,
a little of the black rice.
Mm, fantastic.
-Thank you.
Whole, grilled snapper.
The way Ivan does it,
the spices,
it separates itself
from the meat and the bone.
So, here's the deal.
I've looked at this menu.
I mean, there's a lot on here.
I'm trying to stick kind of
to the Haitian dishes.
So I wanna get Haitian
with a little influence,
so tell me about the --
No, don't tell me about this.
When we come back, we're gonna
do one of my all-time favorites.
You're gonna love it.
See ya in a bit.
All right, I'm gonna get this
and a place to lay down.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Here we are at Ivan's, uh,
Come Cook at My House.
What do you call it?
Ivan's...?
-Cookhouse.
Anyhow, we're in North Miami
at this fantastic
Haitian, Caribbean...
Asian, you know,
you name it all.
You name it all,
and he calls it the Cookhouse,
but I think it's more like
coming to his house.
Got a griot
coming up right now.
It's incredible.
All my friends
that I brought here
from other places
in the Caribbean,
they love his cooking.
It's an explosion of colors
and flavors and taste.
Grilled octopus shallot.
Octopus is a common food
in Haiti.
The way Ivan does
the octopus,
it's very tender,
very flavorful.
It just melt
in your mouth.
I know we don't see octopus
a lot on "Triple D,"
but octopus is one of my
hands-down favorite, so.
-Let's do it.
-We caught that earlier.
No, we didn't.
-Now, first,
I'm gonna do
some mirepoix.
A bunch of fresh thyme.
-Living on the edge, we are.
-Some parsley.
-Okay.
-Some cloves. This is allspice.
-Got it.
And then you just put
that baby boy right here.
His day went from bad to worse.
How long?
-About, you know, 45 minutes.
-Let it cool?
-Let it cool and then cut it.
-So we're not eating the body?
-No.
-We're gonna grill it?
Gonna grill it, first,
and then we're gonna make
a beautiful salad with it.
Okay.
-We got some red onions.
Capers with a little
juice, you know,
for the salty flavor.
Right, right, right.
-Some arugula.
Olive oil.
-Okay.
Crushed red pepper in there.
-A little salt?
A little salt.
It's about time you're
doing something, man.
I know, I know.
-It's about time.
Next, we're gonna just
get the octopus in a bowl.
Okay.
-And then toss it.
And, now, you get
little tomatoes.
Octopus salad right here.
-There we go.
And then I just
do something like this.
Okay.
♪♪
Oh oh, that's good.
A little bit
of that baby arugula.
Brightness of the caper,
fresh-cracked pepper.
But I'll tell you something:
you don't want too much going on
because the octopus itself
has just got such great flavor.
Outstanding, Chef, really.
-Thank you.
-Delicious.
Pick up
grilled octopus.
It is juicy,
nicely seasoned,
and you want to have more.
Pick up
honey-glazed salmon.
He's a great chef.
It reminds me of Haiti;
that's why I keep coming back.
FIERI: It's delicious, man.
You've delivered.
A little island paradise.
-That's it.
-Well done, buddy.
-Thank you, Guy. Thank you.
♪♪
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking
for you next time,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
So, let's -- let's talk
about this.
♪♪
Tug of war.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪