Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you ridin' shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
This trip...
Fire in the hole!
...we're digging in
to a worldwide culinary journey.
This is amazing!
First, a true taste of Africa...
Mmm. Mmm!
...served up
by a San Francisco chef...
I don't want
this dish to end.
...who also rocked it
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
If I lived down the street,
I'd be here every day.
Then a funky
Los Angeles joint...
You're doing something
nobody's touching.
...putting Filipino flair
on good ol' American classics.
It's a grilled cheese
plus, plus.
And in Minneapolis...
This is where
it gets gnarly.
...real-deal Indian...
Get it in the pan
before I eat it all, Chef.
...taking fresh flavors
to a whole new level.
Is anybody at home
tripping out about this?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
You know,
there's something going on
with these "Triple D" joints
and the restaurant owners
naming their restaurants
after animal parts.
Let's see,
like The Whale's Rib in Florida.
Then we had Clove and Hoof
in Oakland.
We had The Shaved Duck
in St. Louis.
I mean, the list goes on and on.
So, here I am
in Koreatown in Los Angeles.
You know what you get?
You get Belly & Snout.
Order up.
Chicken Adobo Grilled Cheese.
Belly & Snout is hands-down one
of the best spots in Koreatown.
Oxtail chili dogs.
It's delicious.
The flavors are addicting.
I don't always
get Filipino food,
and when I want it,
I have to come here.
We're in Koreatown,
but this is Filipino.
Yes.
Filipino-American.
Which means since 2014,
owner Warren Almeda has been
mashing up American faves with
traditional Filipino flavors.
Chef Warren,
he knows what he's doing.
He's doing
the Filipino people proud.
Order up. Sisig hot dog.
Sisig is different types
of porks --
the belly, the snout.
On top of
a traditional American hot dog,
and then garnished
to perfection.
-Yeah, how do you say it again?
-Sisig.
All right. So, this is the pork
snout, and this is pork belly.
A little bit of salt,
a little bit of garlic,
and then add the water.
-How long's this gonna simmer?
-About 3 hours.
This was a traditional dish?
This is a traditional dish.
It goes well with beer.
Everything goes good with beer.
So, we've got our cooked,
cooled pork snout, pork belly.
And now we're gonna grind it
for the Sisig.
Now what?
So, we're gonna add
the bell peppers,
jalapeños, red onions.
Then we're gonna throw it
on the flat top.
-Where we at now?
-So, this is the garlic crema.
This goes on everything.
A little bit of oil.
A bunch of pureed garlic.
Garlic powder.
And a ton of salt.
We're gonna cook it off
for about 20 minutes.
Really?
So it's almost gonna caramelize?
-Yes.
-Mix it with the crema?
Yeah.
Grade-A sour cream.
No Grade-B here.
All right, this is
the Sisig hot dog --
beef hot dog,
garlic crema --
-Whoa.
-Sisig.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Pickled red onions.
Beautiful.
Sliced red radish.
Green onions.
Calamansi.
-Whatever that is.
-It's a Filipino citrus.
We grow it in our backyard.
-You grow that in your backyard?
-Yeah.
-Throw in some chicharrones.
-And more crunch.
The snout's
what it's all about.
It eats bigger than probably
any hot dog I've ever had.
The dog itself
is really good.
The pickled onions play in.
The garlic sour cream
definitely adds some flavor
and a little acid.
But that Sisig right on top?
It's crunchy. It's tender.
It's unctuous. It's fatty.
It's just a really nice
complement to it.
I want a whole sandwich
of that.
MAN:
It has so many layers.
Every bite, you get a really
good combination of stuff.
Order up.
Longanisa Grilled Cheese.
I've been following Chef Warren
since he had his food truck.
FIERI: And even though he traded
in the streets for a structure,
he's still keeping
that original vibe alive.
You're still picking up
from the window.
Order up.
Pork Adobo Grilled Cheese.
Ah, the grilled cheese
is so bomb.
-Oxtail Tater Tots.
-So good!
-What are we into now?
-The Oxtail Chili Tater Tots
and the Pork Adobo
Grilled Cheese.
Like Mexican pork adobo?
-Filipino pork adobo.
-So, this is the Filipino part.
-Okay.
So, we have cubed up pork butt,
soy sauce,
sugar cane vinegar,
bay leaves, pureed garlic.
And then black pepper.
This is gonna cook
for three hours.
-Till it's shred, pull-apart.
-Till it's shreddable, yeah.
-What's up next?
-This is oxtail chili.
We're gonna add the oxtail.
-Not chopped, just the oxtail.
-Yep.
Garlic cloves.
One whole red onion.
Salt and pepper.
Water.
Cook this for six hours.
Then shred it.
A little oil. Garlic.
Mirepoix.
Now we're
French-American-Filipino.
-Red chilies.
-Mexican.
Flour.
Spanish paprika.
Sweat this off
for about 20 minutes.
-Next?
-Black beans.
Green bell pepper.
Oxtail stock.
-The oxtail stock.
-The braising liquid.
We'll let that reduce
for 20, 30 minutes.
-Okay. Next up?
-The peanut butter.
-In the chili?
-Yeah.
I got issues, kid.
And now the oxtail.
So, how long
is this gonna cook down now?
For another hour.
We're gonna reheat
our pork adobo
to put on top of the cheese.
Garlic crema on top.
Now here's
the Oxtail Tater Tots.
Ohh.
Then we're gonna garnish
with Cotija cheese,
a little bit of garlic crema,
sliced jalapeños,
a little bit of cilantro.
♪♪
It's a grilled cheese
plus, plus.
Super creamy.
That garlic sour cream's
in there.
The depth of flavor
that you add with this adobo
really takes it
to the next level.
It's just a really
well-seasoned, delicious pork.
Thank you.
The tots are cooked perfect.
The oxtail
just screams flavor.
Not typical chili.
Matter of fact, you're getting
no American chili flavor.
But what you are getting
is just deep-down gravy,
meat, comfort,
a little bit of spice.
I mean, it just works you.
-Dynamite.
-Thank you.
Pork Adobo Grilled Cheese,
Oxtail Tater Tots.
I've had a lot of grilled
cheese, but none like this.
So, this is Brian Lando,
one of my really good friends,
and he's also
the Executive Producer with me
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
So, tell me what you think.
Tater tots are crispy,
but the oxtail is soft,
so both textures work great.
You should think
about doing food television.
-Order up.
-I love Belly & Snout.
It's the crown jewel
of Koreatown.
Little place. Fly by it.
You'd never know you passed it.
But a ton of flavor
coming out of it.
You're doing something
nobody's touching.
-Thank you.
-Excellent.
Coming up in San Francisco...
Huh!
...an Ethiopian chef
mixing in some Mediterranean...
The dish is
outrageous, Chef.
...and even a jambalaya twist.
All right,
let's do it all again.
♪♪
So, I'm here on the southeast
side of San Francisco
in an area known
as the Bayview District.
I'm here to check out a chef
that's competed twice
on "Triple G."
I was so impressed
with how he competed,
I have to check out
his restaurant.
This is Radio Africa & Kitchen.
Seared ahi tuna, table 4.
This is one of a kind.
Hi, guys.
Vegetable Alicha.
Just a fantastic place
that draws people in.
Like a message from Africa.
FIERI: Delivered by a native
Ethiopian, Eskender Aseged,
who opened this place in 2012
to honor his roots.
29 years ago, we walked out
of Ethiopia on foot --
-You literally walked out.
-Walked out of there.
That's right.
Three weeks to Sudan
and then the United States.
What's the food here
at Radio Africa?
My food is inspired
by Red Sea
and Mediterranean Sea countries
in a Californian style.
Hi, ladies.
Here's your short rib.
The food that you get is fancy,
but it comes out
in a very unassuming way.
Chicken Jambalaya in the window.
The jambalaya
is so absolutely wonderful.
Very different
than the Southern jambalaya.
So you're taking Louisiana and
going right over to Ethiopia.
-That's right.
-All right, let's get going.
-We de-bone the chicken thighs.
-All right.
Then we take, also,
the chicken tenderloin.
That's gonna be
cooked separately.
When you see
chicken fingers,
typically come from
the chicken tenderloin.
That's right.
We're gonna marinate it.
Get salt and pepper. We got
fresh thyme, fresh oregano.
All these come
in the community garden.
-Really?
-Lemon juice. Yeah.
Pomegranate,
and a little bit of olive oil.
I got to be honest, Chef.
I didn't see you move this fast
in "Guy's Grocery Games."
No, I was paying attention to
what other chefs were making!
So, we have this
on top of the chicken thighs.
-Okay.
-And the tenderloin.
And we marinate it overnight
or for a couple of hours.
So, how are we gonna cook
the chicken thighs?
Grill it lightly,
like about 10 minutes each.
-Got it.
-Well, the next thing is,
-we're gonna mix a Berbere mix.
-Burberry --
Isn't that a nice shop
that my wife shops at?
-[ Laughs ]
-Love it!
Bird's eye chili.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion.
Cinnamon.
Cardamom.
This is Ethiopian basil.
-Ethiopian basil.
-Yes.
How is it different?
When it's dry,
it still keeps the flavors.
And then black pepper
and salt.
We mix it up.
-That's the house Berbere mix.
-That's right.
Now we're gonna put
a little olive oil.
Here's our chicken tenders.
What would this dish
be called in Ethiopia?
Chicken Wot, W-O-T.
Next, we're gonna add
the chicken thighs.
Tomatoes --
roast 'em, chopped 'em.
Okay.
With a little bit of Berbere
added to it.
We put the whole thing
in here.
Now we add the mixture
of basmati and brown wild rice.
And then add a little sea salt,
the kale, Swiss Chard,
the spinach.
There you are.
Please enjoy.
You remember Troy Johnson?
Was he a judge
when you were cooking?
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Troy Johnson would say,
"Do you think it was a good idea
to put the Berbere
on the chicken?"
-Absolutely.
-"It was a great idea."
[ Laughs ]
You're welcome, Troy.
The depth of flavor --
It's very inviting.
It's not spicy.
The greens
are nice and vibrant.
The chicken is tender.
The veggies are dynamite.
The Berbere, that little mix --
Oh.
Spot-on.
Mmm. Mmm!
Here's your Chicken Jambalaya.
Just the juiciest, most
succulent chicken I've ever had.
Great vegetables,
freshly picked. I love it.
You know when you see a movie? I
don't want to go see the sequel
because, well, the sequel's
not gonna be as good
as the original movie.
Well, that's kind of
where I'm at right now.
I'm at Radio Africa & Kitchen
in San Francisco.
When we come back,
he's got two more dishes
we're gonna rock out.
Maybe I should just
stick with the one.
But you tell me
these other two are dynamite?
Absolutely.
Then we'll be back.
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're in San Francisco,
hanging out at a "Triple G,"
"Triple D" legend.
This is my buddy Eskender,
and we are at
Radio Africa & Kitchen.
We just had an outrageous dish,
and I said,
"Let's not do anything else.
Let's just go out on a bang."
And he says, "No.
I got two more dishes
that are gonna rock the house."
So, what's the next dish?
Seared ahi tuna.
There's a chermoula sauce,
which is wonderful.
-Chermoula sauce. Okay.
-That's right.
We have chopped parsley
over here.
Cilantro.
Garlic.
Cumin and coriander.
The cayenne's gonna be
just a little pinch over here.
-[ Laughs ]
-Then we have olive oil.
Lemon juice.
Coarse salt and pepper.
I will put this in a blender.
[ Blender whirs ]
Good idea!
Take the lid off!
Are your ears all right?
What?!
[ Chuckles ]
That works for me.
We're gonna sear
the tuna here.
-Sushi-grade ahi?
-Absolutely.
We put a little bit of salt
over here.
And pepper.
We put now the shallots.
-Shallots.
-Garlic.
-Ginger?
-Ginger, yeah.
And then we have
a little bit of turmeric.
Blanched carrots.
Boiled potatoes.
-Cauliflower.
-The cauliflower.
Green beans.
And then the cabbage over here.
We put a little salt, oil.
This is turning into a meal.
We cut this for two people.
Meaning "Don't eat it all, Guy."
The chermoula is what's gonna
go from it here.
-And then...
-Ohh.
-Micro cilantro over here.
-Right.
These are micro cabbage.
Here we are.
-Beautiful.
-Bon appétit.
Mmm.
This dish is outrageous, Chef.
I mean outrageous.
-Thank you.
-Super flavorful tuna.
But the chermoula comes through
with all that huge flavor.
You get a little acid,
get a little garlic,
get a little spice.
I don't want
this dish to end.
And the seared tuna
with chermoula.
Toothy and alive and fresh,
and the whole thing is this
bright confetti of flavors.
You used all the words
in my vocabulary.
[ Laughs ]
Super fresh,
like everything he serves.
Chef Jodi and Eskender
competed together
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
His plates were really
well-presented,
and I was scared of him.
[ Laughter ]
I was.
Which is no surprise, with
dishes like this up his sleeve.
We got saffron prawns
with harissa at the window.
The saffron prawns are amazing.
It's the special sauce
that he puts on it. I love it.
This dish
is inspired by Spain.
We have shelled and de-veined
prawns over here.
-They're de-veined and divine.
-[ Laughs ] That's right.
Now we're gonna make a marinade.
Saffron, little chili flakes,
a tiny bit of salt,
ground pepper,
a little bit
of chopped parsley over here.
-Okay.
-Garlic.
A little bit of olive oil
right here.
A squeeze of lemon.
Mix this.
Let that go
for a couple of hours.
That's right. The real fun
is when we use the harissa.
-We're making harissa, too?
-Yeah, we're making harissa.
Is this like the "Greatest Hits"
album going on right now?
We have red and yellow
bell pepper, garlic,
chili flake over here,
lemon juice.
-Lemon juice.
-The Japanese mint,
caraway seeds,
cumin over here.
Now we add a little oil.
Fire in the hole!
[ Blender whirs ]
We're gonna cook
saffron prawns.
You want to just, like,
barely cook.
Nothing worse
than overcooked.
Chopped parsley,
and then we have the harissa.
-And that's it?
-That's it.
Really nice shrimp.
Nice texture to them.
But when you
get into the harissa,
and then you get
some of the parsley,
little of that minty basil,
a touch of the heat,
it makes you want
to eat it slow, savor the bite,
let all that harissa
kind of open up in your mouth.
If I lived down the street,
I'd be here every day.
Here's your saffron prawns.
They're luscious. When you
bite into them, they pop.
Vegetables with green lentils.
It's not only the food. You have
to enjoy yourself in the place.
The shirt that I'm wearing today
says "The Boss Man."
Mike Hardin is his name,
and he was on "Triple D"
in a place called Hodad's.
Mike had the same passion,
the same energy, and the same
humility that you have.
-Awesome, Chef. Awesome.
-Thank you.
All right,
let's do it all again.
[ Laughter ]
We'll start that up again. Yeah.
FIERI: Up next,
a Minneapolis hot spot...
I just had to get in there
and get out.
...where a rock-star chef...
Outstanding dish.
...is spinning
India's greatest hits.
If you don't think
you like Indian food,
let this be your visa.
♪♪
So I'm here in Minneapolis,
one of the first cities
of "Triple D."
You got the people,
the culture, the food.
So I'm here to check out a joint
that's making
Indian food accessible
to all the great people
of Minneapolis.
You're gonna love it.
This is Gandhi Mahal.
♪♪
Fresh shikh kebab is ready!
It's one of the best
Indian restaurants
this side of New York.
MAN: Dewani Handi Bajee.
The food here
is like Indian soul food.
It's the closest to home
that I can find.
Salmon Tandoori.
Ruhel does a great job
sharing his culture
and foods from Bangladesh.
FIERI: Which is something
owner Ruhel Islam swore to do.
2008,
I become a U.S. citizen.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
So, when I took
my citizenship oath,
judge says, "We want you
to bring your culture.
We don't want you
to forget your culture."
And, boy, did he get it going!
Within that same year,
his family-run restaurant
was up and ready to go.
Chicken Tikka Masala ready!
Tikka Masala,
one of my favorites.
The chicken
is very tender and juicy.
I love Tikka Masala,
so learn me.
This is Halal
chicken breast.
Tandoori Masala.
Coriander powder.
Cumin powder.
-Curry powder.
-Some garlic and ginger.
-Methi paratha.
-Now, what is this?
It's a fenugreek leaf.
-Fenugreek?
-Yes.
Chili powder.
Cinnamon powder.
-Canola oil.
-You going in?
-You have to go --
-Want me to hold your feet?
[ Laughs ]
Look at all the great colors.
You should smell it.
Homemade yogurt here.
-How much salt?
-Four spoon kosher salt.
The lemon, just --
You squeeze it, and then you
-just drop it right in?
-Yes.
How long will this marinate,
Chef?
12 hours.
Then we'll get it
on the skewer,
throw it in the tandoor
for 10 minutes.
But we're also gonna
make the sauce
that goes
with the chicken, correct?
Yes.
So, start with the canola oil.
-Onions.
-Whoa.
-Really? All that?
-Yes.
Garlic, ginger, cloves.
Cinnamon. Cardamom.
Curry powder.
Garam Masala.
Got the whole
Indian spice kitchen going on.
Cumin. Fennel seeds.
Whole milk.
Now the almonds?
Sour cream.
So, more
of the fenugreek leaf?
Yes.
Kosher salt.
Now, how long's
this gonna cook, Chef?
Hour and a half.
-We're gonna puree this?
-Yes.
And then we
get the chicken.
Look how hot that is. It's
burning my fingers right now.
I should get it
in my mouth, then.
Now we're going to make
Tikka Masala?
Yes.
Get it in the pan
before I eat it all, Chef.
A little ghee --
clarified Indian butter.
So that is what we made.
Yeah, that's a Masala.
-Put some chicken.
-Okay.
Put some cream.
Oh, I have the same cream
elephant Indian pot at home.
Chili powder here.
-Tomato broth.
-This is --
-More of the fenugreek leaf.
Lemon.
It's ready now.
All right.
♪♪
Outstanding dish.
-Thank you.
-It's got such a depth,
every part of it,
from the richness
coming from the almonds,
the juiciness of the chicken.
Just a kiss of the tomato.
The char from the chicken
being added to the Masala --
Next level. If you don't think
you like Indian food,
let this be your visa, because
I'm gonna tell you something.
You'll only need
a one-way ticket on this one.
Chicken Tikka Masala.
The chicken is like butter.
It's just tasty.
It's just --
I'm sorry. Let me just give you
a little insight.
This cat's also
one of the "Triple D" editors.
So if you're gonna
talk about somebody
that really knows
great food...
What do you think makes it?
You know, the seasoning.
It's not overpowering.
You can't stop eating it.
ISLAM: Lamb Rezala.
Ruhel is so passionate
about good food.
FIERI:
And about sustainability.
He's got everything from bees
making honey on the roof
to an aquaponic system
growing herbs and vegetables
in the basement.
[ Chuckling ] Whoa.
This is amazing!
So, the fish feed the plants,
and the plants feed the fish?
Yes. So they're all
helping each other.
Is anybody at home
tripping out about this?
Unbelievable.
Dewani Handi Bajee ready.
He makes sure that fresh food
gets on the plate.
FIERI:
Like his home-grown produce for
this classic Indian lentil stew.
Dal.
The dal is smooth and just
a gorgeous medley of flavors.
The dal is like the beans
to the Mexican food.
-Okay, let's do it.
-Okay.
I want to dal it in.
[dial]
Some canola oil,
garlic, cumin.
-Cumin.
-Yeah.
Panch Phoron.
That includes fenugreek, cumin,
a little bit
of mustard seed.
The Indian
all-purpose spice.
-All-purpose spice.
-Okay.
Onion.
Turmeric.
Then tomato, salt.
Make it rain up in here.
And then we dump
the red lentils in.
[ Whistles ]
With three buckets of water.
Then we let this cook
for one hour.
Yes.
Okay, so now
we're gonna make the naan.
So it's a naan
leavened bread.
This is where
it gets gnarly.
This goes here.
[ Sighs ]
It's so hot.
Yes. You did it.
[ Sighs ] Did you see
how fast I got in there?
Can I see an instant replay
on that, please?
I just had to get in there
and get out.
-Okay, here I go.
-Okay.
-Brush it with a little ghee?
-Ghee.
Dynamite.
-Let's do the dal.
-Okay.
Butter in here.
Some cumin seed.
We're gonna toast those off?
Yes. Garlic.
So, this is what we made.
-Magic tomato water?
-Yes.
Cilantro.
Love it.
♪♪
Mmm. The only way
I could really describe this
is if you took the best refried
beans you ever had in your life,
that had depth of flavor,
incredible texture...
This really eats like
this is all you need.
Mmm. It's fulfilling.
It's nutritious.
I promise you
you will love the dal.
Naan and dal ready!
We fight over the naan whenever
we come to this restaurant.
It's every man for himself
when it hits the table.
It's like multi-layered
perfection.
Multi-layered perfection.
Lights out.
You just owned the show.
Tandoori Mixed Grill!
I love this place.
It's wonderful.
You're a fantastic example
of the work ethic
and the pride
and the respect of food.
Nicely done, Chef.
So that's it for this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
Is it part
of the music of the cooking?
-Hey!
-Yes.
Ha-a-a!
Ho, hey!
[ Laughing ]
All right.
We'll be here all week,
performing on Tuesdays.