Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Dude, you are pulling out
all the stops.
...we're going for brunch...
On your mark, get set, go!
FIERI: ...to bologna...
Maybe we should just try
a little piece for science.
...to a couple
of crazy burgers.
Oh, I'm so stealing
that one.
Like in a diner in Portland,
Oregon...
Uh-huh!
...where the meat's
getting a tricky treat.
They just start whooping
out some fried-up donuts
and making sliders
out of 'em.
And in...
-♪ Louisville, Kentucky ♪
FIERI: ...one of
Damaris Phillips'
hometown hangouts...
Woo! Thank goodness.
Let me get in here.
FIERI: ...rise and shine
with true Southern comfort.
That is straight up,
legit awesome.
Plus a funky burger joint...
Oh.
...spicing up their sandwiches.
You're making
fermented pickles, are you?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."
I am Damaris Phillips.
And today on "Triple D",
I'm gonna take Guy to one of my
favorite spots in Louisville,
Kentucky, in my neighborhood,
the Highlands.
How'd I do, Guy?
-You did great.
This is Gralehaus.
Order in.
You can't go wrong
when it's done right.
And they're doing it right.
-Biscuits and duck gravy.
Food's just out
of this world.
WOMAN: Southern style,
a lot of the dishes
remind me of my childhood.
FIERI: And that's the vibe
Louisville natives,
Tyler Trotter and Lori Beck
were going for
when they opened this joint
in an old house.
BECK:
Gralehaus was a home.
So we wanted the food
to reflect, sort of,
the things that we grew up
eating that we love.
FIERI: So they brought in
trained chef and Kentucky native
Andy Myers to amp up
and narrow down the dishes.
It's like a brunch menu
served 7 days a week.
Ready to roll on two
fried bologna sandwiches.
There's something about
a fried bologna sandwich
if you're from this region.
And Gralehaus does it so well.
So a fried bologna sandwich
is a brunch item here
in Louisville?
-It is, yeah.
-Yes.
What are you -- what are you
nodding over there?
-I think it's all the time.
-Okay, good.
The first thing that we do
is we make a spice kit.
I've heard it called
a lot of things.
But a spice kit works for me.
-Okay.
Grated nutmeg, dextrose,
black pepper, coriander,
garlic powder,
some, uh, salt,
curing salts,
paprika and then we've got
some non-fat
dry milk powder.
Milk solids, okay.
You know what that's for?
-Emulsifying.
-Brings it together, ties it up.
We add a little
bit of ice water.
-This is all beef?
-Yes.
So we're gonna
take these two,
blend them together
and start grinding.
Sheet tray it.
Partially freeze it.
Cut it. This...
-Ready to roll?
You can get these at
the carnival right here, right?
-Yep.
-Grind-a-geddon.
I'm, like,
resisting the urge
to just reach out
and touch all over it.
Don't do it.
Gonna load this guy up.
So the casing, I just soak it
for a second just to...
Make it a little pliable.
...make it a little
bit more pliable.
Real easy to do that
when we're standing here
and Damaris is singing.
♪ Well, hello, Dolly ♪
♪ It's so nice
to have you back ♪
♪ Where you belong ♪
He's trying to work.
After we case it,
we smoke it.
And what are you
smoking it with?
Cherry.
Fantastic, so some nice,
great color.
We vacuum seal it
and we cook it
in an immersion
circulator
to get the temperature
up to 155.
Dig it. How are you gonna
make that egg, chef?
-Sunny-side up.
-There you go.
That's definitely
not me.
That's going to be
all this girl.
Our house bologna.
Maybe we should just try
a little piece for science.
See how that
sounded official?
Yeah, why not?
There you go.
I'm going to fry this
on the flat top
with a little bit of butter.
That's good.
I could just dip that
in mustard and eat it.
And you know it's even going
to have more flavor
once it heats up.
-We have a brioche bun.
-What kind of cheese is that?
-A New York white cheddar.
-Is it always two
or is it just because Damaris
and I are both here?
It's always two.
There you go!
Little finishing salt.
Cracked pepper,
a little bit of hot sauce,
a little baby mustard greens.
-Look at that.
On your mark,
get set, go.
Oh, my God.
That is straight up,
legit awesome.
It's super flavorful.
This is kind of a cross
between a nice
summer sausage
and a bologna.
The balance
is really great.
And the texture's
the best part about it.
This is dynamite.
-I like the egg.
It makes it kind
of saucy and messy.
I don't like eating a sandwich
that's not going
to run down my arms.
So especially
in the morning, you know.
It hits all of those salty,
savory notes that you want.
It's got a nice
little kick to it.
Bacon, egg and biscuit.
The food's delicious.
The vibe is just so relaxed.
Lori and Tyler definitely have
been innovators in the city.
FIERI: Especially
on this block.
Next door, they converted
an old church
into a beer and dinner joint.
And you guys share
this patio in the back?
We do.
And if you just
can't seem to leave, well,
then they got a place to stay.
The bed and breakfast
is above...
-Get out.
-...Gralehaus.
No, it's not.
Is it seriously?
-Mm-hmm.
-It has 3 rooms.
So you can wake up,
come downstairs,
have a good breakfast.
-The lamb and grits?
-Lamb and grits.
-Right up my alley.
-You like grits?
-I love grits.
-It's not like any other grits
dish that I've had
anywhere else.
FIERI: Lamb and grits,
Louisville style,
coming up next.
Welcome back.
We're hanging out in...
♪ Louisville, Kentucky ♪
-At the...
-♪ Gralehaus ♪
Right around the corner
from Damaris' house.
You know Damaris Phillips,
the winner of season...
Nine!
...of "Next Food Network
Star."
And she is one of our judges
on "Triple G."
FIERI: Now Damaris has got me
at one of her favorite joints,
where Chef Andy is making
every day a weekend.
Instead of reserving brunch
for Saturday and Sunday,
we do it all week long.
Ready for lamb whenever you are.
MAN:
They have great food.
I would definitely suggest
coming out here
and getting
the lamb and grits.
MYERS:
I'm up on two lamb and grits.
It's got that Southern
grits cheesiness.
WOMAN:
And then the lamb on top,
it just takes it
to another level.
I'm making
the lamb merguez sausage.
-Let's go.
-Some kosher salt, paprika,
ground cinnamon, cumin,
ground coriander,
curing salt and give that
a little bit of a toss.
All right.
So what do we have?
-Some lamb belly...
-Got it.
...and some pork shoulder,
rough-chopped garlic,
onions, fresh cilantro
and some mint.
-Mint.
-A bunch of it.
Do you have a little
garden in the back?
-We do.
-A whole wall, yeah.
It's real pretty.
-It's a whole wall?
[ Beatboxing ]Like a wall, up
a wall, with herbs, up a wall.
I was just going to
add the music in edit.
But why not just
let Damaris beatbox it?
You're welcome.
-Now the spice blend.
-This is great.
We add the hot sauce,
some harissa.
And we're going to go
right into the grinder.
I love fresh sausage patties.
It's one of my favorites.
We cook them in the circulator
2 hours at 155 degrees.
So it'll render
some of the fat out.
So you got all that great flavor
left together and now...
-We're going to make the grits.
-I love grits.
I mean, I make grits
all the time at home.
So we're gonna start
out with milk, water.
Then we add
a pound of butter.
-Oh.
-Oh, my God.
This -- this actually comes
with a free gym outfit.
Then we add the grits.
These are going
to take 15 to 20 minutes.
And we season
with some salt.
Then we add hot sauce.
-Whew!
All this cheese going
to go in there, too?
Yes.
Good, man.
What kind of cheese?
Shredded cheddar.
Then we'll just set that
on the back burner and...
-Fire up the sausage.
-Sure thing.
So once we start to hear
it sing a little bit,
we'll put a lid on it.
Want to go straight into
the oven about 9 minutes.
-All right, chef. Grits?
-Now we've got
a nice sear
on our lamb sausage.
Right in the middle
of the bowl.
This half is mine
and that half is Guy's.
All right.
Don't pop that yolk
in my grits, Damaris.
Add a little bit
of finishing salt,
cracked black pepper,
a little bit
of chiffonade mint.
And the last thing
that we put on it
is a little
Ras el Hanout spice.
The old
'zel Hanout spice.
Mm-hmm.
It looks great.
Before you mess
all up...
Guy went ahead
and got his.
The texture on the sausage
is spot-on.
Awesome, thank you.
This has that distinct,
strong flavor of the lamb.
And that harissa
coming through
with that
little spice kit
that you make
really is great.
I don't know what
I'm having more fun,
enjoying this and tasting it,
or watching you suffer.
I know!
I'm dying over here.
-All right, Damaris.
Go ahead.
-Woo, thank goodness.
Let me get in here.
Little bit of that.
You already crossed
the county line.
Sorry.
Woo.
Oh, my gosh.
That egg is
everything on there.
The grits are perfect,
not too heavy.
So you've taken
a Southern staple.
And you've made it grow up
a little bit, nicely done.
Thank you very much.
-I appreciate it.
-Good job to you.
Deep, hearty
but not overly rich.
It's so good.
-Fried bologna sandwich.
-Wow, beautiful.
Gralehaus
is a perfect combination
of new and old Louisville
right here
on the crossroads
of the Midwest and South.
FIERI: She does
love Louisville.
And she's like, "Oh,
you gotta go to Gralehaus."
But it's awesome.
You did right.
I'm impressed.
FIERI: Coming up,
I'm sticking to Louisville...
See you here.
...for a big-on-pig Cubano...
This is getting it done,
my friend.
...and a no-meat feast
going the extra mile.
I've seen a lot
of veggie patties.
This, right here,
is taking it to another level.
♪ We've got grits
and they are creamy ♪
♪ And they're creamy,
we've got sausage ♪
You could come in with, like,
a higher "We've got sausage!"
-♪ We've got sausage ♪
-♪ They've got sausage ♪
Oh!
[ Laughter ]
So I'm here in the NuLu area
of Louisville, Kentucky,
about 5 minutes
from downtown.
This is kind of like
the new restaurant row.
And I'm here
to check out a joint
where a husband-and-wife team,
well, they started in that
trailer right there.
And now they've got themselves
a full-blown restaurant.
Hey, "Triple D" dude.
Is this Grind Burger?
Yeah, kid,
this is Grind Burger.
JESSE: Kombucha pork
with fries, order up.
You can't find burgers like this
anywhere else in Louisville.
I have an Asian pork
sandwich with sprouts.
I can experiment
and try new things.
I see that you got
the kale salad.
-Liz is a business wiz.
-Third ticket.
Jesse is a culinary genius.
FIERI: And together, Liz and
Jesse Huot ditched their careers
and jumped on
the food-truck bandwagon.
One patty led to another.
And now they're totally
brick and mortar.
We crank out a lot
of burgers here, 1,200.
-A week?
-Thereabouts, yeah.
That's a lot of burgers.
FIERI: And it goes way beyond
just ground beef on a bun.
Veggie with fries, order up.
I love veggie burgers.
And this one, like,
has blown every one
out of the water.
Any time I see
a veggie burger,
in memory of my sister, Morgan,
I, uh, check it out.
-All right.
-Let's see what you got.
All right. We start with
ground cauliflower,
ground Brussels sprouts,
ground shiitake mushrooms.
So it's gluten-free
and vegan, too.
Gluten-free
and vegan, too!
Yellow onion, some oil.
I've seen a lot
of veggie patties.
This, right here,
is taking it to another level.
Roast this off to pull out
a lot of the moisture.
Now,
on to the spice mix.
Kosher salt,
smoked paprika, turmeric,
ground sage...
-Sage it isn't so.
Ground coriander,
mustard powder,
black pepper,
curry powder,
garlic powder,
white pepper,
ancho chili.
Dude, you are pulling
out all the stops.
All right. Now
we're ready to mix everything.
I'm gonna start
with the chickpeas,
ground with potato
starch, quinoa.
You're getting mental
with the lentil.
Got our roasted
veg mix,
toasted pumpkin seeds...
-Dude, you don't stop.
-Sorghum...
-You've gotta have your sorghum.
-A little bit of lemon juice.
Dump in the spice blend,
gluten-free oats.
Woo.
You can do it, Rocky.
We're gonna patty it
right up, go around.
Binds together nice.
That's all she wrote.
And down she goes.
So we've got
our patty fried up.
Gonna add our smoked
tomato ketchup
and dress it like that.
Digging everything
about that.
Mm.
That doesn't eat like
any veggie patty I've had,
such phenomenal texture.
You've got crunchy.
You've got nutty.
You've got creamy.
It's seasoned right.
It's hearty.
That roasted vegetable giddyup
that you played?
-Yeah?
-Oh, I'm so stealing that one.
That's a dynamite
veggie patty.
I wanted it to be this good.
-Veggie with fries.
It's a really meaty flavor
even though there's no meat.
You eat a lot
of veggie burgers?
Not a whole lot.
-This one rocks, doesn't it?
-This one is worth eating.
Everybody will get addicted
to one particular burger.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
-This right here, the B&B.
-What is on it?
Habanero jelly.
Amazing.
Southern with fries.
The Southern burger
has pimiento cheese and bacon.
This is my buddy, Cade.
How is it?
It's good.
I love pimiento cheese.
Spicy, but good.
FIERI: And if a burger
doesn't trip your trigger...
Cuban with fries, order up.
FIERI: ...pork belly on
a Havana classic just might.
This is amazing.
It's better than I've had
at actual Cuban restaurants.
What are we gonna make?
We're going to cure
the pork belly.
It'll go on the Cuban.
-Let's go.
We got sugar,
kosher salt...
-Chili flake.
-Chili flake...
White pepper.
-White pepper, got it.
And then we just
give that a little toss.
-Rub that on that pork belly.
-Flip it.
And this is all just
the beginning.
-Yup.
-We've only just...
-♪ Begun ♪
-Thank you.
Set it in the walk-in.
How long are we gonna go?
It just goes overnight.
We've got onion.
Pork belly's ready to roast.
-Okay.
350 for about 3 hours.
Now we got
the fermented pickles
that go
on the Cuban sandwich.
-The what?
-Fermented.
-Oh.
-Hmm.
You're making
fermented pickles, are you?
What's the whole
fermented part?
Uh, you just have a saltwater
solution to lacto-ferment.
Okay.
Let's ferment some pickles.
Throw about half
the cucumbers in the jar.
Mustard seed...
-Mustard seed.
-Bay leaf, allspice...
-Allspice.
Turmeric, black pepper,
coriander...
A bunch of habanero.
Pureed with garlic.
-Okay, then.
-And grape leaf.
And then we're just
gonna fill it
with saltwater,
pack the dill on top.
And how long are
these gonna ferment?
About 5 days.
Pork belly is done.
We've got some
nice fat slices here.
-Beautiful.
-Sear 'em on the flat top
until they're nice
and crispy on each side.
-Got it.
-Lots of butter down.
French bread
on the press.
Honey ham down first,
Swiss cheese,
fat slabs
of pork belly down.
-Fat slabs.
-The rest of our Swiss there,
garlic mayo and standard
yellow mustard.
Fermented pickles.
-Our fermented pickles.
-Okay.
Lot of work for
one sandwich, homes.
Now we're going to cover
that in butter.
Press that about 5,
6 minutes.
Cut that in half.
Serve it with
our Brussels sprouts.
That's
a real-deal Cubano.
There's certain things
that a Cubano has to have --
the right bread, pressed,
a good Swiss,
proper amount of ham...
...and, in most situations,
pulled pork
and the correct pickle.
That's the right acid to cut
through a lot of that fat.
You are delivering on this
sandwich in every category.
That's right at the top.
All right.
I have a Cuban with fries.
The bread has a crispy,
crusty texture.
It just goes so well
with the pork in the middle
that melts in your mouth.
And then the pickles,
they're sorta,
like, sweet and dill.
It's just a great place to be.
This is getting
it done, my friend.
Come on down
to Grind Burger at...
829 East Market Street,
Louisville, Kentucky.
-See you here.
-See, that was good.
-That was good.
That was the commercial,
right there inside of the show.
-That felt so good.
-It -- it did.
I felt magic in that.
FIERI: Up next, a new take
on a classic diner
in Portland, Oregon.
That's a hot tub
of Flavortown.
Changing up chicken
and waffles...
That's a contender for the title
right there, buddy.
...and doubling down on donuts.
Don't be afraid.
So I'm here in
downtown Portland, Oregon.
You know, on "Triple D,"
I think I've seen 'em all,
every kind of diner,
from the North to the South
to the East to the West.
But of course, I come all
the way out here to Oregon
to find a one-of-a-kind.
They say they're part diner,
part restaurant.
This is The Original Dinerant.
O.G. Poutine.
Definitely one of the best
diner-esque places in Portland.
Deluxe burger with bacon
for ya.
It's amazing.
Gravy on food
and breakfast all day,
that sort of thing.
FIERI: Which is a far cry
from the 20 years
of fine dining Chef A.J. Voytko
brought to the table
when he took over the kitchen
of this hybrid a few years back.
It's half diner,
half restaurant.
But we say we're
rock 'n' roll and tattoos.
And he brings that rebel
attitude right to the menu.
Donut sliders
in the window.
WOMAN: It is a hamburger
inside a hot donut.
There's a little
bit of cheese on it.
There's frosting
on top of it.
Sorry, I get so excited.
So you're gonna make
a burger out of a donut.
-Correct.
-Let's do it.
We're going to make
the, uh, donut dough.
We're going to start
with some AP flour.
-Okay.
-Add some sugar, baking powder,
salt, some milk,
four whole eggs.
And we have butter.
It takes about 5,
6 minutes to get
nice and smooth.
Dump it into
a container.
And put it in the walk-in
overnight. Let it rest.
And we're going to roll it
out to make our donuts.
I'm up here
in the land of granola.
You just start whooping
out some fried-up donuts
and making sliders out of them.
-I love granola.
But there's only
so much you can eat.
Ready to rock.
We're gonna grind
our beef for our patty.
You have two different meats.
Little bit of chuck.
Little bit of Norris.
And then brisket
gives it that,
"Hey, girl,"
type of thing to the burger.
I've never had that
before in my burger.
You know what I'm talking about
when you bite into a burger
and you go,
"Oh, hey, girl."
Okay.
All right.
I'm out.
What size patty we giving em?
-Two 4-ounce patties.
-That's a big plate, dude.
-You go big or you go home.
Patties are on the flat
top, cheese melted.
And we're ready to go.
-Hit it.
So we're just going
to split these real quick.
They get a little bit
of mayonnaise,
the burger slider patty,
one there, one there.
Top 'em off.
And then to finish 'em out,
the beautiful glaze.
And there you go.
Don't be afraid.
The contrast, the salt,
the tanginess
of that cheddar,
really nice texture
of the meat.
It's got a nice
little crunch to it,
you know,
that little fried crust
that you get on the outside
of a donut,
like an old-fashioned.
Gosh, this sounds wrong.
Then you have a little bit
of the sweet, not too much.
You put it all together.
And you'll say...
-"Hey, girl."
Have more than two
and you'll say...
"Hey, girls."
Donut sliders
in the window.
MAN:
Donut slider is a surprise.
To have it with hamburger
and cheese is amazing.
This is incredible
with the sweet and savory.
And it's -- it's good.
They complement
each other really well.
The trainer's not going
to see this, right?
No, no, no.
This is one of my good buddies
out of the Bay Area.
Festus played for the Warriors'
championship team, 2015.
And now
the people of Portland
get to adopt you
as their guy.
It's home now.
Portland is home.
It's not so much, "Let's just be
the standard, ordinary city."
It's weird.
MAN: This restaurant
really fits in with Portland.
The clientele is just
as eclectic as the city.
FIERI: Where they're eating this
offbeat meat and sweet mash-up.
Chicken and waffles
in the window.
So chicken and waffles
is a staple in Portland.
I've had chicken and waffles.
But this is
a little bit different.
It has the jalapeño peppers
inside of the waffle.
Okay. So what are we
going to make next?
We are gonna do our version
of chicken and waffles.
We do chicken confit
and not a fried chicken.
And it'll make you say...
This one makes you say,
"Damn."
So we're gonna take
our chicken legs,
gonna put 'em in a pan
skin down,
meat up as tight as they can go
with some kosher salt,
some garlic on there
and then fresh thyme.
And then we're gonna take
the next layer and do it again.
This is going to go
into our walk-in,
allowed to marinate
for 2 days.
So now we've pulled
this out of the walk-in.
So we're going to pack that
into the pan skin-side up.
Okay. And what are you
gonna use for your fat?
Chicken fat and then
extra-virgin olive oil.
That's a hot tub of Flavortown
right there, buddy.
We're just going to do
a quick parchment top.
Cover it with a plate.
Put it in a 225 oven,
4 1/2 hours.
Let it cool.
Pull it out of the fat.
And then it's gonna go
straight into the deep-fryer.
We're gonna make our batter
for our waffles.
Start with some flour,
sugar, baking powder,
baking soda, buttermilk,
six eggs, gonna whisk.
Gonna add
a lot of butter.
That's what makes
waffles delicious.
Put it in the,
uh, walk-in
for about an hour
to let it sit up and rest.
Set up
with that buttermilk?
Load that into our hot iron,
our fresh, local cheddar.
Diced, raw,
fresh jalapeños.
Yeah, they'll give it
some kick.
-There you go.
-Yeah, the good crispy skin.
That's chicken chicharrones
right there.
Uh-huh.
-We'll finish out the dish,
house-smoked maple syrup.
Of course you do.
Confit chicken's just
flat-out stupid, super tender.
You've got enough fat
in there that it stayed moist.
It's a great waffle batter.
You've definitely got a nice
little jalapeño bite in there.
Little bit of the cheddar.
The maple syrup
kissed the smoke.
That's a contender for the title
right there, buddy.
-Thank you very much.
-The chicken skin,
a little bit of maple syrup,
tastes really good.
-It is, like, love on a plate.
-Oysters in the window.
Dinner, lunch, breakfast,
best food in town.
You gotta
watch out, man.
You're gonna lose
that whole exercise state.
You guys are healthy.
You're going to get
run out of town.
And you know what they'll say?
-"Hey, girl. Hot damn."
So was this a great
road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."
-Woo, thank you.
-Ha-ha!
Beat ya, didn't I?
-You did.
There you go.
You were down there
for the catch.
-Behind your back.
-But I shortstopped that.
-Yeah.
-Then go for the throw.