Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Boo-hoo.
...we're channeling
our inner carnivore...
I can already tell
I'm not gonna love this.
...with some
mega-meaty meals.
Don't put it on bread, dude.
Just give it to me.
Like a finger-licking
Louisville joint...
That's no joke.
...winning big
with their barbecue.
That is championship
right there.
And a Hamilton,
New Jersey, café...
A lot going on here
in a little kitchen.
...serving up
sizzling sandwiches.
I got to come to
New Jersey more often.
And a funky butchery
in Portland, Oregon...
It's really fantastic.
It's, like, stupid good.
...where everyday
is pork-a-palooza.
Ridiculous. Don't come here.
You won't leave.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
So I'm here
in Portland, Oregon,
just about 20 minutes
from the downtown area.
And I don't know what it is,
but every time I come here,
I either find a real-deal
butcher shop
or an amazing sandwich joint.
So I'm not too surprised
when I find both together.
And these folks are
all about the swine.
This is Tails & Trotters.
Pulled pork
just went out.
It's wonderful.
I can't stop coming here.
WOMAN: Here we are.
We've got your Reuben.
There's nothing like it
anywhere in Portland.
Smoked chop.
What they do,
what they produce is special.
FIERI: All stemming
from farmer-turned-butcher
Aaron Silverman...
So I've got a Cubano
coming up.
...whose passion for the pig
led him to open a meat shop
that's 100%
smorgasbord of pork.
About 120
different things.
We bring in the whole pig
and use it all.
The result is a unique
northwestern style of ham
based on a special diet
Aaron conjured up.
Their pigs are finished off
with hazelnuts,
which gives off a nutty flavor.
That's what we grow
out here in Oregon.
There's enough hazelnuts to
get these pigs that fat on?
Oregon raises 98%
of the country's hazelnuts.
Now you're in the know.
FIERI:
And you can take your pork
either packaged
or stacked
into signature sandwiches.
Two Grinders, please.
Two Grinders.
Grinder's great.
It's three different meats.
The zesty sauce.
FIERI:
What are we going to make?
We're making ham
for the Grinder.
We start off
with making a brine.
So we've got water, salt.
Sugar.
And then
a tiny bit of pink salt.
Next up?
Toasted
tellicherry peppercorn.
Juniper.
Some whole bay leaf,
whole clove,
and some whole thyme.
We're going to dilute it
with cold water.
Then we inject the ham
with the brine.
Oh, that is
my kind of injector.
I got to get one of those.
And just watch it swell up.
That good?
Yep.
They're going to go
into this brine 10 days.
It'll come out,
we'll give it a quick rinse,
score the fat a little bit,
and 16 to 18 hours
in the smoker.
Dig it.
So we're going to make
our cured coppa...
Cabana.
The Cabana.
Right.
It's from the Copacabana.
That's where we sing
all day long.
Right, exactly.
That's where it's from,
like I didn't know.
It's the money cut. The very top
of the Boston butt.
The shoulder?
Exactly.
Very nice.
So we're going to
make up the cure first.
Need Kosher salt.
Cure number two,
this has nitrate
and nitrite in it.
I was hoping so.
Yeah, there we go.
Toasted tellicherry pepper,
toasted fennel,
some cracked juniper.
Ground bay.
And some dried thyme.
Then we're going to
mix this up.
Rub generously?
And we'll rub generously.
And then into the bag.
You gonna vacuum-seal this?
I'm going to vacuum-seal them
real lightly.
They're going to sit in the
walk-in for about four days.
Pushing out
the excess moisture,
bringing in all the salt
and flavor.
Rinse it off.
And then the aromatics
that we just put on
are going to get reapplied
and then trussed up and hung
between three and four months.
That's amazing, man.
So we've got our coppa
coming out of the aging room.
Aw!
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to
get that loud about it.
We're going to test it.
This is our water activity
meter.
It'll read the relative
humidity of the meat.
What are we looking for?
Under 0.93.
So we're at 0.592.
It's taking 4 minutes
for it to run its test.
Four minutes?
Half of this will be gone.
It won't even matter
at that point.
It's ready to go.
Look at that.
Mmm.
I'm picking up the juniper.
You're definitely
getting all those herbs.
Not overly salty
by any means, but luscious.
I think people should be able to
come in and just have one slice.
There you go.
Just come in and get
a little dab of it.
Okay, let's make a sandwich.
I'm starving.
So we've got our
toasted ciabatta,
roasted garlic aioli,
relish made with
house-pickled fennel
and roasted peppers,
our ham,
some aged provolone,
our coppa.
Ridiculous.
The lonza is going
to be our spicy lonza.
What is the lonza?
It's cured loin.
Don't put it on bread, dude.
Just give it to me.
Little iceberg
with some red onion
and red wine vinegar.
That is up there in the
best grinders I've ever had.
Thank you.
The vinegars,
the pickled peppers,
really nice ciabatta.
The artisan charcuterie...
...and all the time
and attention,
love and respect
that you've given it,
it's really fantastic.
It's, like, stupid good.
You can get a scratch-made
sandwich like this,
local ingredients,
dynamite.
Mmm.
Joey, your Grinder's up.
The Grinder is
my favorite sandwich.
It tastes like
no other restaurant's.
The way pork
should be done.
They put a lot of love
into their products.
FIERI:
But one product was the first
to capture Aaron's heart.
It's all about
Aaron's dream
about American
prosciutto-style ham.
Everything comes down
from that.
You get the sweetness
of their hazelnut finish.
Mouthwatering.
I can't stop eating it.
So this is
a 2-1/2-year-old prosciutto.
I don't know.
Let me try again.
Delicious. It melts
in your mouth.
It's kind of like
meat cotton candy.
Mmm.
It's got some other notes
that I don't typically
taste in prosciutto.
It has a little herbaceousness
to it.
You've done it well.
Okay,
we have your prosciutto.
Everything he does to make
the prosciutto terrific
translates into
the other cuts of pork --
the fresh cuts, the cured cuts,
the cooked meats.
Porchetta up.
The infamous porchetta sandwich.
The belly and the loin
are rolled with spices.
We roll and tie ours
around sausage.
That would be fine, then.
I'll have seven of those.
I keep coming back for it.
FIERI: And so are we.
We'll catch you in a minute.
FIERI: "Triple D" is
in a Portland kind of place
called Tails & Trotters...
Chris, Cubano.
...at a pork-only paradise
serving up whole hog
over 100 different ways.
Whoo-hoo.
We love pork.
[ Laughs ]
Whoo-hoo.
I might have given
a yippee ki-yay, too.
A yippee ki-yay
and a whoo-hoo.
Can I get prosciutto, please?
You can come in here,
grab some stuff to go,
have a sandwich.
We've got a porchetta.
Porchetta is the belly.
It's the loin.
With this great -- it's like
chili verde sauce on it.
Killer.
All right.
So we're going to
make our porchetta.
Got a bone belly loin
here.
Got it.
Our seasoning is sugar,
salt, then we're going to throw
some lemon in there, as well.
So just a really quick cure
with this?
Yep, just an overnight.
We'll rinse it off
and then coat it
with a nice marinade
that is rosemary,
sage, capers,
little bit of parsley,
juniper, thyme,
a whole bunch
of herbs and spices.
So semitraditional.
We want it to be
a little distinctive.
So we roll and tie around
some sweet Italian sausage
we make.
Really? And how are we
going to cook it?
Oven roasted
for a couple hours.
Okay, next up?
Salsa verde to cut
the richness of the fat.
Pretty traditional.
We've got parsley,
lemon zest, shallots,
capers, salt and pepper.
Then, we'll add enough olive oil
to bind it all together.
Gotcha.
So we've got our porchetta
coming off the grill.
We're going
to chop it up.
And we serve this
on ciabatta, as well?
Yes. We've got
our roasted garlic aioli,
little of that salsa verde
that we made.
Don't go light with that,
do ya?
Porchetta comes on.
I can already tell
I'm not going to love this.
We've got a little
arugula salad.
There you go.
This isn't
your average sandwich.
This right here eats
as a full meal.
The pork's
nice and tender.
I like that you have the variety
from the sausage
to the loin
to the bacon.
The bread
is a huge complement.
But it's the salsa verde,
the way that comes in.
Well done, buddy.
Awesome, thank you.
Well done, Aaron.
Man, I'm telling ya, should open
a gym right next door.
Taking farm to table,
taking farm to treadmill.
Ridiculous.
Porchetta for Jolene.
Fantastic, thank you.
You really get what pork
should really taste like
when you bite into
one of these sandwiches.
So I can't come to Portland
without seeing my cousin.
This is my cousin Paul
and his girlfriend.
All right, brother.
What do you think?
It's not just slices of pork.
It's substantial pieces.
There's something
going on in there.
Yeah, exactly.
It's delicious.
This is amazing.
I absolutely love it.
Pulled pork.
The food is awesome.
We have a lot of great
butchers in this town.
But when you want
to come get pork,
you know you're going to
come to Tails & Trotters.
What you're doing and how
you're putting it together,
you definitely treat it all
with a lot of respect.
Ridiculous. Don't come here.
You won't leave.
You should start
a bed-and-breakfast.
FIERI: Coming up
in Louisville, Kentucky...
Holy moly.
...smoking wings
and monster ribs...
Look at the size
of that thing.
Yeah.
...just like momma makes.
Oh, yeah,
I'll do that.
So you know how that food truck
craze is going on everywhere?
Well, I've got one for you
here in Louisville, Kentucky,
where a guy is
a non-food-truck operator.
That means he's got
a food truck,
but it really didn't run.
So he borrows a kitchen from
a buddy of his that has a bar.
But the buddy that has a bar,
well, he's gonna
go out of business.
So the guy borrowing the kitchen
has to take the bar over.
And, well, that's
where we're at now.
This is Momma's
Mustard, Pickles & BBQ.
Half rack of beef ribs.
Everything is phenomenal here.
That's pulled chicken.
Don't really need sauces
on anything.
Burnt ends for you, sir.
I found my barbecue place.
FIERI: Which is something
KC native Chad Cooley
was searching for
when he moved to Louisville.
We wanted some barbecue
that I was used to
growing up in Kansas.
So he and his chef buddy
Jamie Givan
took charge
and bought a food truck,
thanks to a little
Kentucky luck.
Where did you get the money
to do the barbecue?
The horse, Mucho Macho Man.
You were part owner in it.
Yeah.
Seemed like every time
we needed some more money,
the horse
would win a race.
He just kept funding us
as we grew.
Which is out of the truck
and into a restaurant,
smoking up everything
from pork butt to chicken wings.
Ten wings, side
of buttermilk ranch.
Worlds best wings,
bar-none.
Come out perfect every time.
All right.
How do we get into wings?
First we start
with our dry rub.
Okay.
Dried brown sugar.
We add a little bit
of cornstarch
just to keep it
from clumping.
Dried brown sugar?
Yeah. Granulated sugar,
seasoned salt,
garlic salt, paprika.
Like to mix it
halfway through.
Chili powder,
black pepper, white pepper,
powdered mustard,
ground allspice,
cayenne, and my favorite,
the ground cumin.
Do you want me
to go back here
and see if there's any other
spices you didn't use?
We got some more
if you want to add 'em.
Do you use brine
or anything?
They're just going to sit here
with this dry rub?
This is it.
Now, what kind of wood
do you use in the smoker?
We use strictly hickory.
What temp are we
going to run it at?
About 230.
Hour and a half,
bring 'em out, let 'em cool
and then fry 'em for service?
About 2 minutes,
then we hit 'em with
a little more Momma's rub.
We serve 'em
with our buttermilk ranch.
So this is subnuclear
at this --
Whoa!
Pardon me for using the fork.
I know that no self-respecting
chicken wing eater uses a fork.
But these things are
like 9,000 degrees hot.
One of the things
about smoking wings --
and I like smoked wings --
One is that they could
take too much smoke,
and they can just be like
you're eating an ashtray.
Two, people don't
fry 'em enough.
So they don't get
that crispy wing texture
that everybody loves.
Yeah.
What we have right here
is neither one
of those problems.
Thank you.
Juicy, tender,
good smoke, nice rub.
And that's no little dinky
chicken wing, either.
Oh, yeah, I'll do that.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
That's a real wing.
Got wings up.
By far the best wings
I've ever had.
Thick, juicy,
and just very flavorful.
Momma's Mustard, Pickles & BBQ
is one of the better restaurants
that you're going to
find in Louisville.
Why Mustard,
Pickles & BBQ?
COOLEY:
We had a lot of free time
on our hands
because the food truck
wouldn't work.
And the chef's on salary,
so we might as well
get some work out of him.
I had him doing
Momma's mustard and pickles.
FIERI:
Which are Chad's momma's recipes
served up with
one of their big hits.
The beef ribs.
I refer to them
as Fred Flintstone ribs.
There's so much on there,
you can't even eat it all.
All right, brother.
We're going to
do our beef ribs.
Bone-in chuck ribs.
Holy moly.
Yeah, that's one rack.
Getting a little of
the skin off the back.
Getting it done.
Take as much fat off
as we possibly can.
Really, all the way down?
Yeah, we want that
rub to get into it.
We don't want it to have
to penetrate the fat.
And we're using
Momma's rub again on this?
Oh, yeah.
And go to the smoker.
230 for about 5 hours.
Okay.
All right.
Pickle time.
What type of cucumber is this?
We use English cucumbers.
Sliced onions,
little bit of bell pepper.
Garlic.
This is what Momma taught us.
We're going to salt these
and then ice 'em.
And that ice will slowly melt
and just slowly salt them.
It gives 'em a little bit
more of a crunch, we think.
How long does that go?
Two to three hours. Then
we're going to make our brine.
Let's see it.
Start with
apple cider vinegar,
a bit of sugar, mustard seed,
celery seed, and turmeric.
That's where your color is.
Oh, yeah.
Now we can add
our cucumber mix.
Right when they come to a boil,
we'll get a good stir on them,
into the walk-in,
chill 'em...
And ready for service.
Yes.
All right, Hasenpfeffer.
What do you got?
This is Momma's mustard.
Start with apple cider vinegar,
little bit of egg yolk.
A bunch of dry mustard.
And we'll hit the sugar.
Break up those yolks.
And then our standard
yellow mustard.
Mix that.
Put it in the double boiler.
Cook it until it gets
to about 100, 185 degrees.
And it is fantastic.
I put this on cold pizza.
On cold pizza?
Yeah, it's good
on everything.
All right.
Beef ribs
right out of the smoker.
Two ribs for a half rack.
Look at the size
of that thing.
Yeah.
Whoa, look at
the smoke ring on that.
Dude, that is championship
right there.
That's no joke.
Tender, not dried out.
That is a righteous rib.
I like how it's got its own
voodoo going on right there.
Okay, so now
a little mustard?
Yeah.
Oh, that goes great
with that rib.
And the bread-and-butter
pickle,
still enough body to it,
still enough crunch,
good amount of acid,
nice little bit
of sweetness to it.
I like all the onion.
Mmm, that was a good pickle.
That's a real good pickle.
You look at the smoke ring
on that beef rib
and you look at
the size of it,
it's just simple,
straightforward good.
Nice job, buddy.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Got a half rack beef.
They're juicy.
They're smoked.
They're the best beef ribs
I've ever had.
Homemade pickles
are just phenomenal.
The mustard's fantastic.
Very difficult to beat.
Momma's is my favorite
restaurant in Louisville.
We all love it.
And we love them for it.
I've had a lot of beef ribs.
Those are rated at the top.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Well done.
FIERI:
Up next, a Jersey girl
trading computers for cooking...
So now you're starting to
get all techy on me.
...putting her own special spin
on sandwiches.
You got to make people
happy with that.
A friend of mine actually gave
me a small piece of the horse.
Did you barbecue --
Sorry, that was wrong.
Wow, yeah.
We're going to cut that.
That was bad.
So I'm here in the garden state,
New Jersey,
in the township of Hamilton
on Route 33.
A lot of folks use this
to cruise into Trenton
or to commute to New York City.
And when you're going through
and you're looking for a quick,
easy bite, well, you're in luck.
There's a funky little joint,
and it's called
the Jersey Girl Café.
Hot Shelby in the window.
I have ridiculous cravings
for this place all the time.
Barbecue burger,
mac 'n cheese.
I would take a train back down
to Jersey every week
just to come here.
I need a turkey and brie
now.
I adore Kathy.
Got everything?
You're good?
She came from
the tech industry.
I was a computer programmer,
then a systems analyst,
and a project manager.
FIERI:
But eventually, Kathy Rana's
lifelong love of cooking
ended up taking her
from the keyboard
to the cutting board
at her own café.
So you're basically taking
all that smart stuff
and applying it
to the food world?
Including processes
with running a restaurant.
So now you're starting
to get all techy on me.
When talking about processes
in the analytical system
that we'll be evaluating
for the moment...
Carlos, I need
a Jersey Belly Buster.
You can have things in a panini,
in a rice bowl, in a wrap.
Just really creative sandwiches.
I got a kogi steak
on a torpedo roll.
Kogi steak sandwich --
lean beef, Jersey ripe tomatoes.
It's got a wonderful
Asian flair to it.
I'm into this idea.
All right.
We are going to start
with the bulgogi sauce
for our
kogi steak sandwich.
We have diced up pears.
You don't see diced up pears
going into many dishes.
Couple things --
It adds sweetness,
and it's also
gonna add texture.
Diced onion,
chopped scallions.
I got ginger and garlic,
palm sugar.
Okay.
Soy sauce.
Sesame seed,
sesame oil.
A little bit of water,
salt and pepper.
And how long are we gonna
let this cook down for?
About 15, 20 minutes, or until
the pears are nice and tender.
Now we hit it
with the immersion blender?
Correct. We'll chill it
overnight
and hold it for service.
We ready to make
the sandwich now?
Yeah.
A little bit of grill butter.
Gonna start by toasting
the torpedo roll.
The torpedo roll is what we'd
find a Philly Cheesesteak on?
Yes, exactly.
Okay, I got it.
We have top round beef,
really, really rare.
So, like roast beef.
Now we got to add
a little bit of our kogi sauce.
Just enough
to warm it up.
We have a red-leaf lettuce,
a nice red Jersey tomato.
Okay.
Got our steak
all heated up and saucy.
A little bit of
our spicy kogi pickle,
and we're all set.
It's almost like you're eating
a whole Asian French dip.
You got to make people
happy with that.
We do.
The bread's perfect.
The fresh veggie,
the pickled cucumber,
and the tomato
in a bulgogi-style sandwich
is what legitimizes it.
But the real key to this --
that thin-sliced meat,
just so nice
and light and tender.
Nice. Nice job.
Kogi steak in our torpedo.
The steak is marinated
just right.
Hot Shelby
mac 'n cheese up.
Is there anyplace else
like this?
I think it's one of a kind.
FIERI:
Or two of a kind.
RANA: I have two cafés,
both Jersey Girl Cafés.
All right.
The same town?
Yeah.
Figure I'll have some
on this side of the town,
some on the other side
of town.
I could get everybody
that way.
It's kind of like one of those
hidden treasures of New Jersey.
Her paninis are delicious.
Rosie Panini for Marcus.
Really fresh chicken,
arugula.
And the red pepper pesto
is scrumptious.
Okay.
The Rosie Panini.
Why is it Rosie?
I named the Rosie after my aunt
Rose, who was my godmother,
who passed away
a couple years ago.
She was incredibly
encouraging and supportive
and just the person...
So you named the dish
after her?
I did.
It reminds me of her.
We season the chicken breast
with kosher salt
and cracked pepper.
It's going to roast
in a 325-degree oven
for about 20 minutes.
Next step?
We are making roasted
red pepper pesto.
We got our basil.
We're going to process this,
add in our garlic cloves,
Parmesan cheese.
That is fragrant brasil.
Brasil?
We're going to add in
extra virgin olive oil.
Okay.
Roasted red peppers
and goat cheese.
Goat cheese?
Didn't see that coming.
It adds more body
to the sauce.
Makes it a little
more spreadable.
Nice.
Next step?
Roasted chicken breast.
Slice it.
I'm gonna put this on the grill,
get a little color on it.
Okay.
While that's warming up,
I have my ciabatta bread
that we get from Brooklyn.
There's a lot going on here
in a little kitchen.
It is.
And you don't
toast the bread
because you're
going to panini it?
Exactly.
Got it.
Fresh mozzarella
top and the bottom
so it's extra cheesy.
This is our roasted
red pepper pesto
and some nice,
fresh arugula.
Our chicken's
on top of here.
And then this goes
on the panini press.
Hit it.
These things look like
they've had a little bit
of a workout.
It has.
We want to make sure
that the crust
is nice and toasty
and it has nice color
on it.
Gotcha.
Panini is ready.
And what are you serving that
with, a little broccoli slaw?
A broccoli salad, yes.
And there we go.
That's a really good
sandwich.
Good.
Fresh arugula,
homemade pesto,
house-roasted chicken,
and a dynamite ciabatta --
just really good straightforward
on a sandwich.
We have your
Rosie Panini.
Kathy always does
the chicken right.
The pesto, it's like
a nice song and a dance.
It just blends
very well together.
Beach Body Wrap
in the window.
You always know you're going to
get good, fresh, healthy food.
It's like if you made something
at home for your kid.
How'd you find the place?
I own a cupcake shop
up the street.
And she carries my products.
Have you been
on "Cupcake Wars?"
Yes, I came in second
on "Cupcake Wars."
Seriously?
Mm-hmm.
"Sugar Showdown"?
I won.
Nice job.
It's very easy to fall in love
with Jersey Girl Café.
Once you try it,
you'll be hooked.
Well done.
I got to come to
New Jersey more often.
So that wraps this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
Wings were one of the last
proteins we put on the menu.
You know, we started off
with your typical
pulled pork,
pulled chicken, ribs.
Pulled chicken ribs?
[ Laughter ]