Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
There she blows.
...we're going off the rails...
This is like a freight train
to Flavortown, dude.
...digging into all kinds
of winner chicken dinners.
All right,
in the name of science...
Okay.
...one more dish.
...like comfort on a stick
in Palm Springs...
Yeah, this is stupid.
...wings stuffed
to the max in Maui...
That's another level,
buddy.
...along with a jamming joint...
It's showtime
every night.
...where I'm cooking things up
with rock 'n' roll royalty.
Sammy, Mick, Maui,
"Triple D" -- come on.
That's all right here,
right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
♪♪
Guy, we have arrived.
We are here.
FIERI: Yup, that's rocker
Sammy Hagar chilling in Maui.
Sam, Sam, Sam.
I let you drive the car.
Now you're also going to pick
the "Triple D" location?
Well, this is Mick's place.
Mick Fleetwood?
Mick Fleetwood,
as in Fleetwood Mac,
as in Hall of Fame,
greatest drummer on the planet,
good buddy.
Is his food as great
as his music?
Would I take you
to a bad joint?
You have not done me wrong,
my friend. Let's go.
No, sir.
Hey, welcome to Fleetwood's
on Front St.
You're taking over "Triple D"
now, too, aren't you?
I knew that's
what was going to happen.
Let him drive the car,
that's what happens.
He takes right over.
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
You know you're
going to have a good time.
There's a ton of live music,
really good food.
It's a great vibe.
Everyone knows Mick Fleetwood
or Fleetwood Mac.
FIERI:
But they might not know that
he's been gigging his own joint
since 2012,
bringing the world of great food
and rock 'n' roll together.
I get asked very often about,
"What are you doing this for,
the restaurant experience?"
There's so many similarities.
Your audience, your customer,
it's the same diff.
It's very familiar to me.
It's showtime every night.
And rumor has it --
[ Laughs ] No pun intended --
the menu takes center stage.
Looking at romesco.
Where is it?
...with Chef Eric Morrisette
rocking the kitchen,
following Mick's lead.
Food up in the window.
Let's go. Let's go.
He's been around
the world 17 times,
and so all his influences
really reflect into
what our kitchen is.
Including Mick's
greatest influence.
The chicken idea
emanated from Mom.
What's your mom's name?
Biddy Fleetwood.
MAN: I'm having Biddy's
herb-roasted chicken.
Moist, juicy --
it's just a winner.
You're in fancy Maui.
You're at Mick Fleetwood's
joint, and what do you get?
You get some of
his mom's chicken.
That's it.
We're going to make our marinade
for our chicken breast.
We try to keep it simple --
fresh parsley,
little bit of fresh rosemary,
fresh chive, fresh thyme.
We're going to
finish that off
with some extra virgin
olive oil.
Great way
to get it started.
Very herb-heavy.
We're going to take
our airline chicken breast.
The airline breast meaning
keeping that drumette
of the chicken wing
connected to the breast.
Range-free?
Oh, yeah,
always fed properly.
Are you
into organics?
I am increasingly so.
My lifestyle did change.
[ Laughing ]
We've been sharing
some rock 'n' roll stories.
Dump our herb marinade
right on top.
Get it under that skin,
and we're going to let it
marinate for 24 hours.
Our next step is going
to be the bagging part.
Mick, I don't know
what the instruments are
that you play with
that when you see one, you go,
"Oh, that is awesome!"
In my world, when I see
an immersion circulator,
it's just...
Brownie points.
That's right.
So, what happens here is,
we keep a precise,
constant temperature
of circulating water
that takes food to its optimum
point that Chef designed.
Keep it at 155.
So we're going to start off.
We got our
24-hour-marinated chicken here.
Get inside that bag.
A little bit of smashed garlic.
From there, we add
a little bit more thyme.
About a tablespoon
of butter.
Now, if I eat this,
will I look this good?
Is that what happens?
You go to that level?
Kid's doing
it right.
Exactly.
So, now we take this,
put it in the vacuum sealer.
So we go ahead
and drop it right in the water.
How long is it
going to go?
About an hour
and 15 minutes.
Sous vide
under pressure.
Correct.
Boom.
Dig it.
All right, Chef, you're cooked
through, but not overcooked.
In my world,
that would be "in tune."
Nice!
And now we're
going to crisp the skin.
Skin side down.
Bring it fully to
temperature for service
and blow people's mind
with the jus?
Absolutely.
We start off with
a little bit of fennel,
bay leaf, thyme.
From there, we deglaze
with some white wine.
Let it reduce down,
and then we're going to
add our chicken stock.
I know you've tasted
this enough times, but...
Going in.
Okay.
You know what this is?
That's chicken
French onion, baby.
That is
chicken French onion.
There you go.
I love it.
You'll hit it with the jus.
Let that jus reduce.
We're going to start
plating up our chicken.
Bit of buttermilk mashed potato.
We have some fresh local kale.
We're going to go ahead and get
our chicken right on top there.
And then here's that jus.
There we are.
As Biddy would say...
"It's crispy."
[ Laughter ]
Mick, I think
you've had this before,
so I will dig in first.
You go in. Go in.
You didn't need a knife
on that, by the way.
I could have just cut that
with my laser vision.
That's -- Yeah.
Chicken that
is ridiculously tender.
Righteous chicken --
like, real-deal chicken.
A tremendous amount
of flavor,
the herbs are just
screaming through this.
The kicker is the jus.
It just
carries it all together.
It's just so silky.
What do you call it, Mick,
when you play a tune
that's just so easy?
It's like
a harmonic convergence.
Everything is right,
in balance,
and you're happy.
I see why your mom
liked it, Mick.
Amen.
Awesome job.
Do you eat this often?
Oh, very often.
Go ahead and have
a little dig in.
Get right in there.
There you go.
Huh?
Biddy would be happy?
Love it. Love it.
Good man. Good man.
Walking up, we got one chicken.
I want this thing out.
Let's go.
Meat is so tender
and juicy -- exceptional.
I love the jus.
Jus got to be kidding me.
[You]
There's never a flaw
every time I've eaten here.
You've got the rooftop lounge
that overlooks the ocean.
Pretty much the coolest place
in Lahaina
to hang out
and have a drink.
So, you got
another dish for me?
I know you got to get
ready for rehearsal.
We'll let the boss go.
See you in a bit, brother.
Thank you very much,
Mick.
Good, 'cause I got
to decompress for a second
'cause I'm losing it.
I'm going to eat
my nervousness.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: And pork belly
just might be the cure...
So many flavors.
It's just amazing.
FIERI:
...when we come back.
♪♪
FIERI:
So, I'm hanging out here
at the legendary
Fleetwood's on Front St.
in Lahaina, in Maui.
The man was in here.
Oh, yeah.
How awesome
is it having Mick?
Oh, forget it.
It's wonderful.
WOMAN: If you know Fleetwood Mac
and you know Mick,
he brings a lot to the place.
It's got rock 'n' roll.
It's got a great menu.
Here we go. We have
beautiful pork belly here.
The bourbon-glazed pork belly,
it is phenomenal.
It just melts
in your mouth like butter.
All right, we're going to do a
little bit of pork-belly brine.
We're going to start
with a little bit
of bay leaf
and peppercorn...
garlic...
fresh rosemary...
fresh thyme...
kosher salt...
a little bit of honey.
When the honey pours
like that,
you know
it's hot in the kitchen.
Water.
Now, how long are
we going to let this go?
Just to a boil --
kind of get those aromatics
working a little bit.
Then hit your ice, cool it down,
drop the pork belly.
How long are we
going to let it brine?
I'm going to brine it
24 hours.
Now we're going to hard-sear it
in a cast-iron pan.
There we go.
I'm going to go ahead
and put in some mirepoix
and tomato paste,
then deglaze the pan
with chicken stock.
Fantastic.
Braise it off
about 4 hours.
From there, flip it over
fat side down.
Make our blocks.
Beautiful.
We have a little bit
of olive oil in our
smoking-hot cast iron.
This is one portion.
Go big or go home.
Or just go home big.
Yeah.
Hard-sear all directions.
Hard sear, hard sear,
hard sear, hard sear.
Matched with
a little bit of bourbon glaze.
From there, we're going to start
plating our stuff up.
This is a little bit
of Dijon mustard,
maple syrup,
and a little bit of mayo
to just kind of bind it
all together.
Add a little bit
of Brussel chimichurri.
I'm not going to make it
out of the door.
Two pieces of pork belly
on top of there.
A little bit
of pickled beets.
It's a nice acid,
a little bit of sweetness.
And some candied pistachios,
and we're done.
Look at all that
unctuous fat.
It's delicious.
Truly ridiculous glaze.
Some dynamite
Brussels slaw.
It looks high-end.
It eats comfort.
I mean, come on, man, you guys
are in the land of swimsuits,
and then you're
feeding people pork belly.
It's legit as they come.
Outstanding.
Congratulations, man.
Thank you.
How long on that pork belly?
CHEF: Two minutes.
MORRISETTE: Two minutes out.
My favorite part is definitely
the richness of the pork belly
complemented by
the nice, crunchy slaw.
The bourbon glaze just gives
an extra dimension of flavor.
Come on, guys. Let's start
moving these tickets.
We're starting to get
behind a little bit.
There's something
for everyone on the menu.
Before you go, you got
to try the Wellington.
Fillet of beef wrapped
with prosciutto
and a pastry around it.
This is a signature dish here,
really.
All right, in the name of
science, one more dish.
FIERI:
And this one's got Sammy Hagar
written all over it.
Say, where can a guy get
something to eat around here?
This just came out of the oven,
and Sam shows up.
Look at it.
It's like a baby.
You eat that,
and you won't drive 55.
You'll drive,
like, 35.
No,
that's for two.
We're going to start off with
a little potato. Why not, right?
A little bit
of Brussels sprouts.
We get the smoked pancetta,
a little bit of mustard
in there, as well.
We're going to cut
our ends off,
go right down the center,
one nice slice.
Forget it.
Aw, dude.
Right on top.
Demiglace.
Yep.
Got it.
Get on in there.
♪♪
That's delicious.
Mmm-mmm.
Come on.
Mmm. Fresh. Oh.
It's that
medium rare in there.
See it right there.
Mm-hmm. Bam.
You can't take
Emeril's "Bam."
How about "Boom"?
You can have "Boom," Sammy.
[ Laughs ]
The food's legit.
You got to come and try it.
You know great food.
Sammy knows great food.
I listen to the man.
Love it.
Great job.
You're awesome, Sammy.
Thank you, brother.
Come on.
This is righteous.
Really dynamite.
You're a dangerous,
dangerous person.
I never want to see you
again until tomorrow.
Ah, next week.
Next week.
[ Laughs ]
MORRISETTE:
Oscar, let's talk about
that Wellington.
That Wellington, man,
was -- Whew!
The pork belly
is off the hook
There you go.
...the sous
vide chicken, brother.
You two, can't thank you enough.
I love it, brother.
Thank you, man.
Mick, thanks, man.
It was awesome.
Thank you.
Really appreciate it.
Boom.
MAN:
If you're a fan of good food,
good entertainment,
this is definitely
the place to come.
[ Mid-tempo music plays ]
Sammy, Mick, Maui, "Triple D" --
come on.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up, we're still
hanging in Hawaii...
Ohh!
...to check out an island
Thai food truck...
I don't even want to tell you
how good this is.
...stuffing the wings...
What will they
think of next?
...and bringing down
the house with the pork.
It's ridiculous.
The food is...
better than the music.
Oh! Welcome to Fleetwood's
on Front St.
[ Both laugh ]
♪♪
I'm telling you what, man --
old habits die hard.
I'm here at the food trucks
right by the Maui airport,
and you know what
I'm looking for --
the awesome fresh catch
I got last time I was in town.
Hey, Danny.
Ahi poke bowl, man.
Sorry, brother.
We're all out.
You're killing me, dude.
Okay, so where do I eat?
Go check out Thai Mee Up
right down there.
He's unreal.
Ask for Tommy.
Okay. I get it.
This is Thai Mee Up.
Here's the
lobster curry noodle.
I love it.
It's Thai-inspired island food.
The satay chicken is finished.
WOMAN: We're right by
the airport,
so it's perfect
for right when you land.
I'm here at least
three times a week.
FIERI: The guy bringing
customers back is Tom Sribura,
whose German dad
and Thai mom
ran a restaurant
back in Thailand.
What type of food
do you do?
SRIBURA: You know,
I love local food,
and I really like
Thai food.
So local Hawaiian
and Thai together?
Yeah, together.
SRIBURA: Here's your
stuffed chicken wing.
Today, I got the
stuffed chicken wings.
The chicken is really moist,
perfect texture contrast.
It's stuffed with pork, shrimp,
and vegetables and noodles.
What culture makes
a stuffed chicken wing?
Thai people actually
make quite --
Stuff the chicken wing?
Yeah.
So, we're going to start
by making the stuffing.
Start with the oil.
Okay.
Ground pork.
And this is a dish
your mom used to make?
Yeah,
one of my favorites.
Now we're going to add
the shrimp and the garlic.
I have not seen it when it's 1:1
garlic to shrimp and pork.
Brown sugar.
Thai people
like sugar and spice,
so we add
the black pepper.
Oyster sauce and fish sauce,
commonly known as Thai vodka.
Thai vodka?
Thai people love fish sauce.
Oh, I love fish sauce.
Oh, yeah.
I'll have a rubber boat
burrito of that.
Yeah.
We're going to mix
the pork with the cabbage,
carrot, and rice noodles.
Okay.
We're going to debone
our wing now.
And that's it. Just boned and
now you're going to stuff it.
We will steam it.
So it gets cooked
all the way through.
All right.
So, we've got our chicken wings.
Now we're going to dredge
it in the AP flour,
in the egg wash,
in the panko.
Chicken's going.
How do we get it together?
It's coming with
a scoop of rice,
the tofu and watercress
salad right here.
So we got the stuffed chicken
wing and the plum sauce.
You make the plum sauce?
Yeah.
What's in the plum sauce?
The plum, I guess.
Oh, the plums --
[ Laughter ]
What will
they think of next?
♪♪
I don't know, bro.
That's out-of-bounds.
All the time and energy
that you put into making that
really comes out.
The shrimp still is
nice and tender.
The noodles, garlic,
the black pepper,
that plum sauce --
that's another level, buddy.
Thank you.
It's very surprising to have
that all mixed into it
and still be crispy
and very tasty.
Sautéed with a little garlic.
Tom's reputation
precedes him.
People come here because
they know his work ethic.
FIERI:
Sweating out in the food biz
for over 20 years...
May I have some noodle,
please?
...before debuting
his own righteous rig.
Can I borrow this to haul
my car around?
Yup. That's what it
used to be before.
MAN: Tom has done
an amazing job
building his trailer
and building great food.
Here's the boneless pork rib.
Enjoy.
The boneless pork ribs
are definitely my favorite.
I love the flavor.
I love the texture to it.
And he gives a very good,
large portion of it.
What are we doing now --
boneless pork ribs?
Yes. We're going to make
the marinade for it.
Okay.
Curry paste
and sugar...
Mm.
Chili soy.
A lot
going on here, buddy.
Yup.
We're going to add
the fish sauce and soy.
This just gets
better as we go.
Garlic, lemongrass,
and Kaffir lime.
The Sri Lanka leaf.
So, we mix all that up, and what
kind of pork do we have?
We got
regular pork butt?
We're using
regular pork butt, yeah.
How long are we going
to marinate the pork?
For at least 6 hours,
And then...
We just drop it
right in the deep fryer.
Next up?
Now we're going to get
the garlic lightly roasting.
I love garlic.
Literally 4 tablespoons
of garlic.
Now we are ready
to finish up the pork rib.
We're going to add
a little black pepper to it,
fresh Thai basil,
Kaffir lime leaf,
cilantro and green onions,
and we finish off
with the soy.
Nice big scoop of rice.
Lots of papaya salad.
Ohh!
One of my favorite things
in the whole world
is papaya salad.
It's good?
And pork rib.
♪♪
I don't even want to tell you
how good this is.
It's ridiculous.
Thank you.
The meat's super tender.
The flavor balance is awesome.
You get the spice.
You get the vinegar.
You get the garlic.
On a flavor scale
of 1 to 100, that's 101.
And then you cleanse
your palate...
with the papaya.
Mm-hmm.
Bro, this is one of the best
things I've had on the island.
Oh, thank you.
Ever.
SRIBURA: Boneless pork rib.
Pork ribs are tender.
MAN: And a lot of garlic,
so if you're a garlic lover
it's one of the go-to dishes.
Tom does a lot of great stuff
in a casual setting.
You're very humble
and very cool about it,
but what you're
turning out of here,
this is like a freight train
to Flavortown, dude.
You are the man.
Thank you so much.
Bro, super impressed.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
in Palm Springs...
Isn't that cute.
...a funkalicious
hot dog haven...
What a fun joint, man.
...changing it up
on a couple of classics.
Prime time, bro.
I mean, prime time.
Thank you, man.
♪♪
So, I'm here in
South Palm Springs, California,
and a road known
as South Indian Canyon Drive,
and this was the main
drag back in the day
when everybody would come from
Los Angeles for spring break.
You can find every kind
of restaurant through here.
So, what am I looking for?
A hot dog joint.
And this is it -- Frankinbun.
♪♪
Let me get
a Bacon Frankin-Ripper.
I get a lot of cravings
for this place.
Everything I've ever had
has been awesome.
WOMAN: Portuguese Hawaiian.
Different tastes than anything
you'll find in Palm Springs.
FIERI: Courtesy of owner
Tristan Gittens...
GITTENS:
Currywurst looking great.
...a hot dog lover at heart
who happens to be
an epidemiologist by trade.
You have a real job here
and then a hobby.
A little research here
and there,
study cancer --
things like that.
No.
But his greatest achievement
might be finding a way
to go meatless
with an American classic.
GITTENS: Vegan chili dog up!
The spice in it is so good.
I love it.
WOMAN:
They really do a good job
of getting that meat flavor
in there.
Vegan sausage.
Okay.
The spice mix has got
everything under the sun.
Allspice, fennel, cayenne,
oregano, paprika,
black pepper, garlic powder.
Red chili flake.
Got it.
Mix it all up.
We soak and cook
black-eyed peas.
You mush it up
a little bit, yep.
Little mash?
Onions and garlic and mushrooms
cooked down.
Spices.
Brown rice flour,
nutritional yeast.
That yeasty flavor --
I got it.
Olive oil,
gluten-free Worcester sauce --
costs a million dollars
an ounce.
Does it really?
And then tomato paste.
So, mix it up. Just leave
a little bit for texture.
4-ounce balls,
put them in cellophane.
Steam them.
So, they'll congeal.
They'll tighten up.
Yeah.
Then we'll
grill them later?
I cook it in a pan.
Has its own
little vegan pan?
Yeah.
Isn't that cute.
Next?
Vegan chili.
We're going to sweat
all the vegetables.
Where were you last night?!
[ Laughs ]
A little bit of oil.
Oh, that way.
Sorry. My bad.
Get the onions working,
garlic,
and then celery,
and I like to cut it real thin.
Red bell pepper,
and then I like it spicy,
so a lot of jalapeño.
Let that work down
for another 5 minutes,
and then we start
adding everything else.
Chopped tomatoes,
vegetable broth,
red wine vinegar,
a little bit of tomato paste.
Where'd you learn
these recipes?
Just experimenting.
And now we do the spice.
Chili powder, cumin,
cayenne, oregano,
salt, cilantro.
Cooks down
for about an hour.
And then beans soaked
overnight,
then cooked down
for about 2 hours.
We put this in at the end and
cook it for another 30 minutes.
And that's it.
Build this vegan dog.
I like to use
a whole wheat bun.
You said you want
a little ketchup?
We make our own in-house.
It's very spicy.
A little mustard.
And then our chili.
A little bit of our
homemade sauerkraut.
That's our vegan sausage.
Oh!
Good?
Dude, right off the bat,
let's just go to the sausage.
Incredibly flavorful.
The chili's legit.
No one would ever
be able to say
that the chili was meat chili,
not chili.
You got tomato,
you got sweet.
And then...
you get that little snap
from this acid
of the sauerkraut.
That's one of
the best vegan dishes
I've ever had on "Triple D."
Wow.
Prime time, bro.
Thank you, man.
I mean, prime time.
Thank you.
GITTENS:
Vegan chili dog -- ready.
I like it because it doesn't
taste like a vegan dog.
One of my favorite chefs,
Mark Tadros,
he and his family
own a date farm
and make hundreds
of thousands of pounds of dates
that they ship
all over the world.
So, what do you think?
I think it's great.
I want to take another bite.
Sauerkraut puts it over the top.
Chili's nice and spicy.
WOMAN: Frankinbun is
a fun place to stop.
It's casual. It's eclectic.
It's colorful.
When you walk in,
you're going to see
this really funky wallpaper
that you happen
to also be wearing.
That's our
little hot dog guy.
A design your wife drew?
Yep.
FIERI: And the creativity
doesn't stop
with his wardrobe
and wall coverings.
WOMAN: Chicken and waffles
on a stick.
Completely took me by surprise.
One of my favorite dishes.
Chicken waffle dog.
This is our thing.
Okay.
We make our own mix.
Flour, cornstarch,
baking soda,
baking powder,
sugar, salt.
Got it.
Now we're going
to do the wet mix.
Milk, oil...
egg --
just the yolk --
and vanilla.
He does things very
doctor-like, doesn't he?
Wet to dry.
Yes, we will, Doctor.
Now we whip
the egg white.
All right,
so the whites go in.
Yep.
What's the chicken
that's going in this?
Bavarian chicken apple.
It's like a little
breakfast sausage.
Look at those
little buddies.
Throw them in the batter.
The waffle machine is
in the shape of a hot dog.
Oh, I got to see this.
I hit it
with a lot of oil.
Add a little batter.
Two to an order.
Down, spin, 4 minutes
on the time clock.
All right.
Four minutes.
There you go.
[ Bell dings ]
Are we ready?
There she blows.
Whoa!
And then we serve it
with real maple syrup.
Dude, that's way more
than chicken and waffles.
The batter's great.
The maple syrup is
a nice little give.
Yeah, this is stupid.
That is an extra
hour at the gym.
Can't say enough about it.
I would order it over and over.
Mika, I have known since he was
a baby, grew up in Santa Rosa,
and now he's going to college
down here in the area.
What do you think?
I actually really
liked it.
It all works together.
And, like, super sweet,
but really good.
WOMAN: If you're coming
to Palm Springs,
you should definitely
check out Frankinbun.
The effort and the time
and the energy
and the enthusiasm and the fact
that you love it so much
and you wear a hot dog shirt,
that all works for me.
It's really legit.
Glad you enjoyed it.
What a fun joint, man.
Thank you so much.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
We whip the egg white.
By hand?!
Yeah.
I got to go
check on my car.
All right.
Hey, kid!
Get off my car!