Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners, drive-ins,
and dives.
This trip...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
...buckle up
for the real deal...
Bring it!
...as we dig into
some multicultural cooking...
Anybody that watches
"Triple D"
knows I don't typically eat
the entire plate.
...like in Orlando...
Oh, my gosh.
...where we're going
from a crazy pastrami project...
I mean, like,
that level of pastrami.
...to a righteous
Puerto Rican pinchoria.
This might be my Puerto Rican
brother from another mother.
Plus, in Houston...
Wow. That's
all I can say.
...authentic Mexican
I just wasn't expecting.
I don't get surprised
very often.
Today,
I've been surprised.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Houston, Texas,
about a mile from downtown
in an area known as Montrose.
You can find it all here.
They've got boutiques
and wine bars and restaurants,
cool little place to come to.
And I'm here
to check out a joint --
and I got to be honest
with you --
I don't know if I'm prepared.
See, from what I've been told,
this place is
real-deal Mexican
like I've never seen before.
This is Cuchara.
Chilaquiles blancos.
It's an adventure in my palate.
Beautiful flavors.
Tostaditas de tinga.
It's not where you come in
and sit down
and you get chips and salsa
brought to the table.
FIERI: Because in the land
of Tex-Mex joints,
owner Ana Beaven is staying true
to her south-
of-the-border roots.
Is that kind of
the whole attitude here
at the restaurant?
Yes. Show what Mexico
really is.
If you've never been to Mexico,
never had the food,
this is exactly
what you would eat.
FIERI: Like this authentic twist
on a Mexican staple.
BEAVEN:
Four-corn tortillas.
I get excited looking
at the tortilla. [ Laughs ]
I love that thing.
It's fantastic.
All right,
what are we making?
The four-corn tortillas.
We're going to make
the masa from scratch.
I've seen mortar pestles,
molcajetes.
I've never seen that.
Metate.
We use it for corn.
We use it for peppers.
We use it for spices.
First, we take
the fresh corn,
and there we go.
And this is what they say,
you know,
the corn starts
crying or something
because it releases
all the water.
This is called martajado.
It's broken,
but it still has water.
That's when it's ready to blend
with the corn flour.
And then water.
And then work with your hands.
Voilà.
Okay, now, we're going to build
the other three flavors
of the tortillas.
Yes, we're going to build
the black-bean one.
These have been
previously refried with lard.
Where is this
traditional at?
From Michoacan.
They make it for holidays,
for different kinds of parties.
It's a specialty.
I mean, I thought
I'd seen everything
in the world of tortillas,
but that is
a whole nother world.
Now the poblano
with the cilantro?
Mm-hmm.
So, it's previously
blended together.
So, it's got
enough of the water.
Mm-hmm.
So, now we have
the verde done.
And now the guajillo?
The guajillo.
This one, we have to strain.
In the world of dried chilies,
this is my favorite.
And this is
a lot of the time
what you find
in enchilada sauce.
No other pepper
gives you this color.
Oh, this is going
to be awesome.
Now, what's the idea?
Put them together?
Go to the press?
Correct.
We're going to take
our little balls.
Put them right
in the middle.
Got it.
Ever-so-useful plastic.
[ Creaks ]
I like that little noise.
That's gorgeous.
So, onto the plancha
that's already got
its own seasoning to it.
Mm-hmm.
It doesn't need any oil.
Look at that!
That is awesome.
Let's keep making them.
What...in the world...
is this?
It's a liquid salt
from Yucatan.
In a squirt bottle.
It's called "rain salt"
in Mexico.
Rain salt. Okay.
And what do you do with it?
Squirt on your tortilla
and try it.
You'll be surprised.
Am I getting punked right now?
Because this is weird.
So, just
spray this on here?
Yeah.
And then try it.
Try each flavor
by itself.
This is awesome.
Look at that.
I'm telling you.
It's fantastic.
Mm-hmm.
Where --
Is this real?
That is the craziest
stuff I've seen.
I want it in a foot pump.
You've got such a funky attitude
and such a funky style
with so much authenticity.
Outstanding.
Here you have some tortillas.
The best tortilla
I've ever had.
WOMAN #1: Ever time I tried
a different bite,
it was a different flavor.
This is probably my favorite
neighborhood restaurant,
and I eat here
three times a week.
The tacos crujiente
is one of my favorites.
It's crunchy tacos stuffed
with hibiscus flowers.
WOMAN #2: You would think
it would probably be sweet,
but it's a wholesome,
creamy filling.
We have our house salsa,
and then we add a little bit
of Mexican cream.
The hibiscus flower
and cream-cheese tacos.
Ah-ha!
The hibiscus has a little bit
of bitterness to it,
but then the crema balances
it out with a little sweetness.
Correct.
And then the salsa.
It's burned peppers
and burned tomatoes.
Wow. I mean, just
flat-out outrageous.
Hi, guys,
how're you doing today?
I love this place.
I think I actually have eaten
everything on the menu 20 times.
I have one more taco
I want you to try.
Bring it.
Tacos chelo for 31.
Flavorful, crunchy.
Very unique.
FIERI: And I'm digging into
this dish after the break.
Top 10 best tacos
I've ever had.
FIERI: At Cuchara restaurant,
just outside
of downtown Houston,
owner Ana Beaven has steered
clear of maracas and margaritas.
You wouldn't call this
your typical Tex-Mex restaurant.
No. Not at all.
This is authentic Mexican.
From the decor,
the artwork that Ana's sister
has designed
for the restaurant.
All the little dishes that they
brought over from Mexico City.
FIERI: Which is also where
this recipe comes from.
Tacos chelo.
FIERI:
Okay, what is tacos chelo?
Well, I'm going to tell you
who Chelo is first.
Chelo is
a super-mean lady
that has been
selling fried tacos
on the streets in Mexico City
for like 40 years.
The best taco stands,
a lot of times you go there,
they don't talk to you.
Exactly.
They just make the tacos.
But it's worth it
because the tacos are the best.
Is that the kind of place?
That is the kind of place.
So, we have potato.
It's already boiled.
We're going to add
a little bit of butter.
Some chopped epazote.
So, how do you describe
the flavor of epazote?
Like an intense perfume.
It's got a tang,
a little bit of sourness to it.
It's just magic.
And then we have...
Raw onion....
...onion. Yeah.
A little bit of salt
with pepper.
So, we're going
to take the tortilla,
put a little bit
of the mix of the potato.
We're going to roll
them like flautas.
And that's it?
We fry those up?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Does the mean
Chelo lady know
that you have tacos
named after her?
She actually smiled
a little bit
when I told her
how popular they are.
No!
Okay, next up?
We're going to make
the green salsa.
So, tomatillos.
These have just been
cooked down?
These are boiled.
Boiled, okay.
Cilantro,
boiled serranos,
garlic, salt and pepper,
a little bit
of raw onion.
Get it.
And that's
all she wrote?
And then
we have to cook it.
Oh, we're going to cook
this still?
Yep. Especially
because of the raw garlic.
Tasty.
So, we have
the tacos ready,
then lots of salsa.
Just because it's going
to soak it all up.
We add cotija cheese,
and then we add raw onion.
All yours.
That's phenomenal.
I've had so many great tacos
so many different ways,
and what you've made,
flavor-wise
and creativity-wise,
stacks up.
Top 10 best tacos
I've ever had.
Wow.
That's all I can say.
Anybody that watches
"Triple D"
knows I don't typically
eat the entire plate.
That takes the cake...
or the taco.
It takes the taco.
The crunchiness
of the tortilla
with the creamy potatoes
in it is just fantastic.
So, my buddy, Mark,
and his daughter, Kensley,
from the great state
of Texas,
have you had anything
like that before?
It's very unique.
Very unique.
Good heat,
though, right?
Mm-hmm. The right amount
of heat. Unbelievable.
WOMAN:
Just something different
from what you typically get
in Houston.
One of my childhood
heroes, Dan Pastorini,
played for the Oilers,
played for the Raiders.
This is like we are
south of the border.
Yes, it's special.
It's a unique taste,
you know, wonderful food,
great atmosphere.
It's like you're walking into
your own private city of Mexico.
I've been doing this
for a long time,
been to
a lot of restaurants.
I don't get surprised
very often.
Today,
I've been surprised.
I think the beauty
of what this restaurant
does is it reminds me,
as a chef and as a fan
of ethnic food and culture,
that there's so much
more than what we know.
I just tried three things
I'd never tried before,
and I will tell you this has
been an outrageous experience.
Good.
You are fantastic.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up in Orlando...
I like the way
this is rolling, boss.
...a tricked-out food truck...
You are really a scientist
about what you're making.
...gaining
some serious mileage
with their
Jewish deli dishes.
Dude, that's no joke
right there.
♪♪
I'm here in Orlando, Florida.
I love this state.
Got great weather.
You've got a real
eclectic mix of people,
and with a mix of people
like that, you get great food.
So, when I hear there's a dude,
and he is doing
New-York-style pastrami
out of an old tool truck,
well, you know I've got
to track it down.
This is The Pastrami Project.
Good morning!
I'd like a pastrami
sandwich, please.
This is a whole new
pastrami experience for me.
Reuben taco!
I ate one and brought home
three more.
Lox and a bagel.
George has brought
New York to Orlando.
FIERI: Literally,
because owner George Markward
and his wife, Debra,
make it a point to study
classic New York Jewish delis
and the tradition
behind them...
I went and looked up
old recipes,
old ways and techniques
of doing it.
Everything I'm doing here
is the way
they did it
100 years ago.
All of George's dishes
are authentic,
remind me of growing up.
FIERI: ...with pastrami taking
center stage.
You bite into it,
and it just melts in your mouth.
Mm-hmm.
Something different about it.
Okay. Let's do it.
We're going to make a brine
for an approachable-size
piece of pastrami.
Approachable?
Yeah.
Not the 80 pounds I put
in the brine at a time.
80 pounds in at a time?
Oh, yeah.
We've got to start
with pink salt, allspice.
Coriander.
Whole cloves,
whole black peppercorn,
nutmeg, mustard seed.
We have bay leaves,
red-pepper flake,
ginger, cinnamon,
a little bit of sugar,
kosher salt,
garlic cloves.
Are we going to
let this simmer?
We let it
simmer and melt.
Okay, then we're going to ice it
or going to cool it?
We're going to ice it.
Ice it so we don't
poach our meat.
Exactly.
Got it.
How long will
the flat sit in here?
A week.
Really?!
Mm-hmm.
Let's see
what we've got.
All right.
Beautiful brisket.
Then it gets a dry rub
of black pepper and...?
Coriander.
Coriander. Got it.
I like a lot of flavor.
We really rub it in.
Both sides or just one?
All sides.
There we go.
What are we smoking with?
Hickory, which is what
they would have used
up north 100 years ago.
What temp are we
going to run at?
About 225,
about 5, 6 hours.
This is hot.
What are we serving on?
Rye bread
with spicy mustard.
Oh! I'm such
a pastrami junkie.
My mouth just --
You can hear
the sirens going off.
Even Croc Dundee
would tell you
[Australian accent]
that's a knife.
That's what you use
for cutting pastrami.
See how there's
a little bit of juice.
That's a normal portion?
Yeah.
That's pretty much
a normal portion.
Oh, my gosh!
Give it a try.
See all the juice
just come running out of that?
That's ridiculous.
Mmm!
Very tender.
You're not confusing it
with a lot of other stuff.
I was scared to death you were
going to put that slaw on there.
The key to it is,
right inside of here,
all the fat's been
rendered down now,
so it's just to the point
of being liquified
to where the fat mixes
with the meat,
and every bite you get is
just creamy delicious.
Oh, my God.
It's so good.
I mean, like
that level pastrami.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
It is tender, it has got a nice,
peppery taste to it.
MAN: The bread, the meat,
just the mustard
reminds me of back home
in New York.
Come on up!
George is
an interesting guy.
Absolutely.
He's very knowledgeable,
very creative.
FIERI: Especially
when it comes to his truck.
Did the Partridge
family have this?
No, this was a tool truck
in its first life.
I built this thing
by hand.
What did you do
before that?
I was an IT guy.
There's a variety
of electronic components.
Well, I'm a geek.
You tinker?
Oh, big time.
Which means, of course,
you've got to tweak around
with the menu, too.
We take the ingredients
of a Reuben
and turn it into a taco
or a egg roll.
But at the base
are the standards.
We have beef brisket,
latkes.
MAN: If I find him
for breakfast time,
I always go
for the bagel with lox.
The lox are very tasty.
It tastes like it was
swimming a few days ago.
All right, boss.
We're going to
make some lox.
Got it.
Salt and sugar.
Equal amounts.
There's kosher salt
and table sugar.
Please don't use anything
but kosher salt.
Table salt,
it will turn gray.
What's going to happen
is this is going
to season the fish,
but it's also going to
pull the water out of this.
Some lemon.
And then if you want
the flavor of juniper,
the easiest way
to do it is gin.
So, you drink it
and then just pour it on?
No.
Oh, okay.
How long is it going to go?
Seven days?
36 hours.
That's it?
That's it.
Okay, let's do it.
Salmon has come out...
Rinse it off.
Nice and firm.
We've just got to get you
a nice portion of it here.
I like this. You pulled all
the pin bones, right?
Yeah.
What are we
serving it with?
A bagel
with cream cheese.
You do want capers
and onions?
I like the way
this is rolling, boss.
Dude, that's no joke
right there.
It's no joke.
Here's the beauty of it.
There's not too much salt,
not too much sugar.
You didn't overdo it
with all the flavorings.
Mnh-mnh.
You really get
to taste the salmon.
I've had really
good lox in my life.
To think that
you're making this
in three days
here in the truck --
They're dynamite.
Absolutely supreme.
It was fantastic.
It tastes genuine.
It's like having
New York in a truck.
Great food, great company.
You take everything
very lightheartedly,
but you are really a scientist
about what you're making.
I call the project
a success.
Thank you.
Well done.
FIERI: Up next,
we're sticking to Orlando...
Look at this!
That's it!
...for a Puerto Rican spot...
That's good mofongo,
buddy.
...where the plantains are
delivered in a one-two punch.
Basically, we're going to
make bread out of plantains.
So, you've got
the sword from Conan,
the hat
from Indiana Jones,
and the Doc Brown look from
"Welcome Back to the Future"
or "Welcome Back,
Kotter"
or "Welcome Back
to the Future, Kotter."
♪♪
So, I'm on the east side
here of Orlando, Florida,
and a buddy of mine says,
"Hey, guido,
I know how much
you love mofongo,
and I know much you
dig funky joints.
I've got the place
you've got to check out."
This is Willie's Pinchos.
GARCIA: Pick-up for four
pinchos, please.
I'm from Puerto Rico,
and since the first time
I came here, I love it.
It's kind of become
a comfort food for us.
From the first day
I walked in here,
I was treated like family.
FIERI:
Courtesy of Willie Garcia,
who left Puerto Rico at 15
and went from dishwasher
to owning food trucks,
to opening up this brick and
mortar with his wife, Jesenia.
You guys, enjoy.
What kind of restaurant
was this before you --
It used to be
a pizzeria.
It was a pizzeria,
and now it's a pincharia.
It's a pincharia.
And what does
pinchos mean?
Pincho means a skewer,
meaning a stick.
On a stick?
Yes, sir.
Pinchos are ready to go.
FIERI: But they're not just
putting out pinchos.
They're firing up all kinds
of traditional
Puerto Rican fare.
Pick up of carne
frita mofongo, please.
Today, I'm having
the pork and the mofongo.
The pork is tender
on the inside,
yet it's crispy on the outside.
Mofongo is mashed plantains
mixed with garlic and oil.
It's perfect all the time.
What are
we going to make?
We're making the mofongo
with the pork fry.
Mofongo first?
Yes, sir.
So, you get
the plantains in.
We put in hot water.
Makes them
easier to peel?
Yes.
Nobody told me that!
That's why you're learning
here today.
Look at this!
Look, that's it!
So, we cut it in chunks,
and then we fry them
for like 7 or 8 minutes.
All right, Chef.
Now we're going to
make the house mojito.
We take the garlic.
And we're going to use
this to season the pork?
Exactly.
Couple spoons of salt,
pepper, and garlic.
It's adobo.
I call it adobo, too.
So, we mash it down
like that together
and 5 ounces
of vegetable oil.
This is pork butt
that's boneless.
And then we do it
overnight.
And then we're going
to fry it off?
Yeah.
All right, let's put it
together, man.
All right, each mofongo --
two head of the garlic,
a couple of teaspoons
of the adobo.
And then
we mash it first.
Then we go with
the mojito again,
and then we get
the plantains.
I can already smell it.
Then we get the pork out.
Just give the onions
a little kiss.
Take it like this, and
you go for it like ice cream.
Look at that.
It's not too wet.
It's not too dry.
Got it.
Put it right here.
Then we get the pork,
we drizzle a bit of it
with the mojito.
Tastes really good
with the onions.
Mmm!
And then we got
two piece of bread.
And then you get
your cilantro sauce,
and you get
your mayoketchu sauce.
Mofongo.
Ah, that's
good mofongo, buddy.
I've never seen it
with the cilantro sauce.
So, just different people
have different ways?
Yeah, we don't
play with the rules.
Delicious.
Mofongo has to be pureed,
but you still have
to have big pieces.
So, you get soft, smooth,
and then something
that's almost crunchy
like a pretzel nugget.
I really like a good piece
of fried carnitas.
Yeah.
That has
a lot of texture in it.
Nice job, brother.
Thank you.
The mofongo has got
a great consistency.
The pork is very, very crispy.
I literally feel like I'm
in Puerto Rico eating at home.
Here you go,
tripleta.
And how do you get
into this place?
Because it looks like there's,
what, maybe six tables.
Just wait.
But stick around.
It's worth hanging out
for a few
to get some really good food.
What do you think makes
the food so dynamite?
He just has a great product,
and he delivers.
Pastrami jibarito pick-up.
The jibarito, yes.
Wonderful.
It's like a sandwich,
but instead of bread,
you have plantains.
You have meat, lettuce, tomato.
It's something that
I can't stop eating.
All right. Next,
we're going to make the...?
Jibarito.
The jibarito?
Yeah.
Say it again.
Jibarito.
Yeah.
Basically, we're going to make
bread out of plantains?
Yes, sir.
These are going to take
about 14 minutes to cook.
14 minutes.
Yeah. So, we're
going to grab them.
So, we take Willie Pincho's
ping-pong paddle.
That's the best way to cut it.
And then what we do,
we mash it down,
and then we make that twist.
Why the twist?
You make it bigger.
Okay.
So, now we put them
back in the fryer.
And this is going to be
basically the bread for this?
The bread,
yes, sir.
Okay, so,
what do we got?
So, we got some top round steak
kind of chuck.
So, we would put
seasoning on it.
You just went through
a tenderizing machine.
Yeah.
So, we basically use
the mojito for
almost everything.
Hey, give me some mojito.
Give me the mojito.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There you go.
Okay, how long do we
let that marinate?
For 24 hours.
Okay.
Now, we're going to cook
the marinated steak.
Beautiful.
We put the pastrami
on the flat-top,
and then we put some
more mojito on it,
mustard, and then a little bit
of cheese on the top.
We melt it.
Now, we're going
to sample the jibarito.
We've got the two plantains
right there like a bun.
We go mayo first,
put lettuce right here,
piece of tomatoes
right there.
Then we put
the mayoketchup,
and then we take it
from the flat-top,
and we make it
right there.
Who could eat this?
Oh, you will. [ Laughs ]
We get the potato sticks,
the cilantro sauce.
Bada boom.
You could cut it in half,
or I guess you could do that
thing that you do, the hunch.
The hunch?
It's very delicious.
Pastrami is a nice kick
because you're
not expecting it.
You're going for
these Latin flavors,
and then, all of a sudden,
you get this pastrami kick.
Mm-hmm.
The meat in itself,
top round,
has got a ton of flavor.
The plantain, working
as a bread, is really tasty.
All of the sauces that you
make are delicious.
You've got
more flavor here
than I think most people
would anticipate.
Fantastic.
Good job.
Thank you.
Pastrami jibarito.
The plantain that they use
is really crispy.
It's better than a bun.
WOMAN #1:
My favorite thing, I would say,
would be the steak, especially
with the mayoketchup sauce,
which I love.
WOMAN #2:
Willie's is one of the good,
authentic Puerto Rican places
here in Orlando.
I think you cook
like you like to eat.
Exactly.
That's why I make it.
Trust me. This might be
my Puerto Rican brother
from another mother.
[ Laughs ]
So, that wraps this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Is your real name Willie?
Yes, sir, William.
Doesn't sound
very Puerto Rican to me.
No, I know.
You are really
from Puerto Rico?
I am from Puerto Rico.
Straight up.
Island flavor.
Okay. [ Laughs ]
Island flavor, baby.