Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Both laughing ]
From coast to coast...
Look at that.
...we got a whole mess
of flavor heading your way.
Oh, my goodness. I think this
should be taken away from me.
Like, believe it or not,
a real taste of Switzerland
tucked away in Oregon...
I am really tripping out.
...dynamite dogs in Charlotte
just like you ate as a kid...
Looks like
a hot dog emporium.
...and a grilled cheese
food truck
that'll knock your socks off.
That is a platinum album
right there.
I can hear that playing
on the Flavortown station.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
I say Charlotte, North Carolina.
What do you say?
You say barbecue,
and you're not wrong.
But in a big-hitter town
like this,
you can expect way more
than just barbecue.
So, when they tell me
they got a joint
dedicated to the dog,
well, you know
I got to check it out.
This is JJ's Red Hots.
♪♪
I've got a Char Heel and chips.
I love this place.
I've got a Sonoran
and a Joliet Jake.
It's not your average hot dog.
They are always thinking
of something new.
Looks like
a hot dog emporium.
Thank you.
We take it very seriously here.
FIERI: And owner
Jonathan Luther's
don't-ditch-the-dog approach
started from square one.
On the back of a napkin
on a plate
where I didn't have the greatest
experience with this hot dog.
The idea -- to create a taste
and nostalgia
as good as his favorite
childhood spot,
even if that means
scratch-making his own sausage.
It's called a kasekrainer,
traditional
Austrian-style sausage.
Let's do it.
We got pork butt,
85/15 chuck.
We got kosher salt,
ground mustard.
Okay.
White pepper.
A lot of it.
Little garlic powder,
and a little bit sugar --
a little bit of sweetness.
Gonna go into the mixer.
We're gonna whip it.
Whip it,
whip it real...?
Real good.
Nice guard.
Oh! I was so thinking
about wearing a neck tie
then trying to make sausage
at the same time
and you can't do it now!
[ Chuckles ]
We get that incorporated
a little bit,
then we got to add
the ice water,
take it up a notch here,
and then, this nice, beautiful,
cube Emmentaler cheese.
Emmentaler.
Some aged Swiss.
Now into the big
sausage press.
A natural casing
on there.
Nice and easy.
Link it off.
Yep.
We're gonna
smoke this also.
We do hickory at about 225,
about hour and a half.
All right,
what are we making?
House-made
hot blonde mustard.
Do the voodoo
that you do.
Okay, little ground
mustard powder.
There you go.
Kosher salt, paprika.
Turmeric for color,
little cayenne.
Got it.
Garlic powder, cumin.
Our wet ingredients,
of course.
We have cider vinegar.
Our wedding ingredients?
Wet ingredients.
Wedding ingredients.
Wedding ingredients?
You got to marry
everything together.
[ Both laughing ]
All right, here we go,
cider vinegar.
We have our own
sweet-pickle brine.
Then we do our own
pickled jalapeño.
Got it.
A little bit
of clover honey.
This is our
Carolina Blonde Ale.
What happened? That thing was
full before we started the show.
It sure was.
Finally, our horseradish.
Whoa!
Whisk it all together.
And go on top
of this dog.
Correct.
And why do you call it
the kreishenkrieger --
cracker jacker?
That's what
they call it in Austria.
"Kase" means cheese
in German.
Okay.
And then "krainer"
means krainer.
Oh!
Krainer means krainer.
So, we got our finished
smoked kasekrainer,
and then we just
flash grill it to order.
Kasekrainer right here
on our potato roll.
Then, we're gonna hit that
with a little kraut.
[ Whistles ]
House pickle, red onion,
and then
our hot blonde mustard.
Plate this up now with
our fresh fried onion rings,
hand-cut,
little buttermilk bath,
throw in spice mix,
and that is our kasekrainer.
♪♪
For a dog to be able
to stand up
to pickled red onion
and kraut,
it's got to have
a lot of flavor.
It's got a ton of flavor,
great cheese.
Thank you.
That's legit, man.
There's good snap
of that casing,
the hot blonde mustard
works in there perfectly.
The little char from the grill
is really the kicker.
Right.
And of course, a terrible
onion ring next to it --
give me 9,000
of these, please.
All right, I have
a kasekrainer and onion rings.
Spicy mustard,
tender bratwurst -- Oh, man.
And the best thing about it
is the cheese in the middle.
Andouille and chips!
The food here is just amazing,
and it's just fun.
This is something
the city needed.
You're from Charlotte?
No, I'm from Buffalo, New York,
originally.
FIERI: Which is where
he gets his dogs from.
Sahlen's in
Buffalo, New York --
fifth generation,
family owned.
And in business since 1869,
an old-school company
for his classic creations.
LUTHER: I got a
chili cheese Coney and chips.
Love the Chili Cheese Coney.
It's just like you ate
when you were a kid.
What are we
making next, boss?
This is a traditional
sort of hot dog chili,
so no beans.
Okay.
Little bit of olive oil
on the pan,
and we start with our
ground beef here.
And we do something
a little different.
We poach it in water.
We're just gonna have it
break apart.
We don't want texture.
Exactly.
It's gonna be
smooth, velvety,
meat sauce is
what you're gonna get.
Correct.
We break down those clumps.
We're gonna let that poach
for about 20 minutes,
then will add the rest
of the ingredients.
Okay, tomato paste.
Ketchup,
little onion puree.
Okay.
Worcestershire sauce.
Sha-sha-sha-sha-sha.
Little cider vinegar.
I got chili powder,
cayenne, paprika,
garlic powder,
black pepper, kosher salt.
And how long is this
gonna cook down?
About an hour,
and then we'll skim all the fat
that kind of rises up.
We got our char-grilled
Sahlen's dog,
little bit of chili,
jack and cheddar cheese,
then some finely chopped
onions on there.
You don't want them
too big.
The chili cheese Coney.
[ Choir singing softly ]
Did you hear them?
What?
Hot dog angels.
Were they singing?
Oh, they were singing.
Turn up your volume
at home.
[ Choir sings loudly ]
Here is what's wrong --
nothing.
Thank you.
Here's what's right --
everything.
The chili's dynamite,
the onions are cut perfectly.
You're right.
You got to mince that onion.
Just for science,
I'm gonna take one more bite.
Of course,
I don't need it.
[ Laughs ]
That char, it reminds me
of the hot dogs you got
when you were a kid.
We're trying to recreate
those memories here.
That is dynamite, man.
-Thank you, man.
-It's a great dog.
Hi. I have a Coney
with house chips.
The chili is fantastic.
End up wearing it a lot.
It's worth however
messy you get.
Takes you back to that
hot dog at the beach,
the hot dog
in the backyard.
It's delicious.
Well done.
Thank you very much.
FIERI: Coming up...
You're really
getting after it.
...a funky joint
in Portland, Oregon....
[ Imitating Swedish Chef ]
...serving up the Swiss
you just can't miss.
Hey, that rhymes.
I can't shovel this
in my face fast enough.
♪♪
[ Car door closes ]
Are you ready to get confused?
All right, check this out.
I'm here in
the Alberta Arts District
of Portland, Oregon,
to check out a Swiss restaurant
that's owned by a girl
that's from Hawaii.
You only find this
on "Triple D."
This is Swiss Hibiscus.
♪♪
Ooh! That's hot.
I love Swiss food.
I never would have guessed it.
It's delicious.
Woman: Ossobuco with
our house-made spatzli.
I'm actually from Switzerland,
and it really
transports me back home.
FIERI:
Because owner Jeanie Wyss
got her cooking jobs
from her Swiss-born dad,
who owned a restaurant
for decades in Honolulu.
I left my nursing career
to do this
as something to carry on
my dad and mom's legacy.
Now he makes trips to Portland
to help Jeanie
and her partner, Tammy Hay.
How is she doing
in the restaurant business?
Oh, she is doing excellent,
better than me.
Better than you?
No!
-Well, she's teaching me now.
-She's teaching you.
Either way, the result
is real-deal Swiss specialty.
FIERI:
What are we gonna make?
Paprika schnitzel
with spatzli.
With what?
Spatzli.
Spatzli?     That's Swiss way
of saying spatzle.
It does not make any sense,
looking at you
and then hearing you say it
with the accent
and talking about a Swiss menu.
I am really tripping out.
Yeah.
So we have
a Carlton Farms pork loin.
Carlton from
"Fresh Prince of Bel-Air"?
That's a long time ago.
Huh?
Mm-hmm.
Gonna cut two medallions.
Tenderize.
Salt, paprika,
and dip it in the flour.
And that's all she wrote.
Okay, we're
gonna make spatzli.
Spatzli.
We have flour.
Make a little well.
Eggs, white pepper, salt,
a little nutmeg, and milk.
Okay.
Now I'm getting to the point
where it's almost mixed,
but really want to slap it.
I think it makes it
a little more fluffy.
You're really
getting after it.
Okay.
♪♪
The water is boiling.
Oh-ho!
I need one of these.
Yeah. Okay.
Did you salt the water?
I did already, yes.
I want one of those
spatzli-matics, like that.
And that's it?
That's it,
let it boil 3 minutes.
And then you will be able
to heat it in the pan
with what,
a little butter?
A little oil and then,
this is our house garlic butter,
my dad's recipe.
Okay.
So, the schpetslay --
Spatzli.
...spatzli is ready.
Now we're gonna cook
the chop.
Yes, both at the same time.
Being a nurse, you sure got
that flip going with that pan.
Practice.
♪♪
White wine.
More garlic.
A little bit
of garlic, paprika.
You're getting after it
with the paprika, girl.
Yep. Brown sauce
from Switzerland.
Your dad bring that over
in his luggage?
Nah, we ship it.
Heavy cream.
Add a bunch
of sweated mushrooms.
Yeah, and put
the meat back in.
Oh, when it gets a little bit
of crunch on it.
Yeah.
♪♪
Traditional garnish --
Chop-chop, we call it,
for chopped parsley.
Okay, a little chop-chop.
And then, flower parsley.
[ Chuckles ]
That's tasty.
I love paprika.
♪♪
I can't shovel this
in my face fast enough.
I want to get down...
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, sorry.
The spatzle --
I can't get it right --
is dynamite.
A little crunch,
little texture.
Oh, my goodness.
I think this should be
taken away from me.
I mean,
It's just a really simple dish.
There's not a lot
going on here.
Really simple, yeah.
But the critical point to this
is doing it right.
♪♪
Your dad's got
to be proud, girl.
Prouder than I think
he thought he would be.
[ Chuckles ]
Paprika schnitzel
with spatzli up!
I can't explain it.
It just tastes delicious.
The sauce is so good,
you could almost drink it.
It's an overall a great dish.
FIERI: And another thing
customers are coming in for
is, get this,
the salad dressing.
It's like a really good
ranch dressing,
but it's a little more tangy.
FIERI: It got so popular
at her parents'
Honolulu restaurant,
they started bottling it
and selling it in stores.
Before the restaurant
opened here,
I would literally
pack it in my suitcase
and bring it back.
If they sold it by the gallon,
you'd buy it?
I'd buy it.
All right.
Let's do this.
Start with garlic, onions.
Now this is
your secret spice blend.
This is what you're not
gonna tell me?
Not gonna tell you
the yellow one.
The other one is
salt and pepper.
Salt and pepper.
-Maggi seasoning.
-Maggi seasoning. Okay.
Mustard, mayonnaise,
and then add in the oil.
And you emulsify it
with that.
Exactly.
Got it.
♪♪
Delicious!
That's tasty dressing.
We always have a bottle
in our fridge.
You got any more tricks
up your sleeve?
Little bit.
Let's see it.
Okay.
We'll see you in a minute.
I'm gonna finish this,
I'll be in the walk-in.
Okay.
♪♪
FIERI: Welcome back.
We are cooking up here at
the Swiss Hibiscus in Portland.
Say that five times fast.
Swiss Hibiscus,
Swiss Hibiscus, Sw-- That's it.
That's as far
as she can get.
Her dad is from Switzerland,
she is from Hawaii,
your mom's Japanese.
Yep.
And we're making
Swiss food.
Gravlax up!
A Swiss restaurant in Portland.
I mean, who knew?
It's very unique.
HAY: Your emincé Zurichoise
with our rosti.
Emincé Zurichoise --
my favorite food here.
Emincé...?
Zurichoise.
"Emincé" is the French way
of saying cut really thin.
But the Swiss way of saying it
is [Speaking foreign language]
Oh, it's good.
It's fun.
Yes. Yeah. All right.
So, we're gonna slice
the pork sirloin,
salt, little white pepper,
flour.
And then rosti is gonna be
your traditional starch.
The what is?
Rosti.
It's like hash brown.
Just call it hash brown.
You lost me at rosti.
My dad's version of rosti
is he adds in
the bacon
and the onions.
That's already precooked here
ahead of time.
Now, these potatoes
have been cooked
about 3/4 of the way,
then shredded.
Shredded, yeah.
Just a little bit of salt.
Pan's nice and hot.
Go ahead and put
the pork sirloin.
Then you shape the rosti so it
stays together when you flip it.
Throw the onions in.
We're gonna take it out
so we don't overcook it.
Overcook it, got it.
Add a little white wine.
Some more mushrooms.
Mushrooms, brown sauce,
heavy cream,
let it reduce
a little bit.
Then the rosti is
ready to flip.
Do you want a drumroll?
You gonna be able
to pull this off in one flip?
I should be able to.
You think so?
You're making me nervous.
Everybody at home...
[ Pounds on table ]
[ Drumroll ]
[ Cymbals crash ]
[ Cheers and applause ]
She's a pro.
You can put just
a little bit of butter.
Okay, back in.
Meat goes back in.
Let it cook
a little bit more.
Rosti going on the plate.
[ Imitating Swedish Chef ]
Just the emincé Zurichoise,
little chop-chop.
Little chop-chop.
I wouldn't know what anybody
would love about this --
a big fried potato pancake,
some pan-seared pork,
little white wine,
some gravy,
and some heavy cream,
a few mushrooms.
Nah, no one would
like this stuff.
[ Imitating Swedish Chef ]
[ Chuckling ]
Very simple food,
really treated the right way.
And you make it
real deal.
Delicious.
♪♪
-It's creamy and delicious.
-Rich and flavorful.
It truly feels like
a little island
of Switzerland in Portland.
Congratulations.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You got to come meet
this girl, for sure.
FIERI: Up next...
Really?
...a legit food truck
in Charlotte...
Out of bounds.
...getting all grown up
with a childhood favorite.
Brother, you giving a lot
of respect to grilled cheese.
I'll wash my hands.
Where did she go?
Hi, welcome back
to the Swiss Hibiscus hour.
I'm Guy.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Charlotte,
North Carolina,
and, man,
do they love their food.
Matter of fact,
they love food trucks.
So, I'm looking
for this one food truck,
and it kind of sounds like
it's a Mexican food truck,
but people tell me no,
it is the real deal
grilled cheese.
This is Papi Queso.
A big cheesy with bacon.
They have the best
grilled cheeses around.
MAN: Golden brown and delicious.
These look gorgeous.
Grown-up grilled cheese
taken to the highest level.
FIERI: That's 'cause
Brian Stockholm's
culinary adventure land
combines 20 years of experience
with a taste of childhood.
So we wanted a product that
people could really relate to.
What makes a grilled cheese?
The texture between
the crunch
and that ooey-gooey center
and that meltiness.
Meltiness.
But this place is throwing
a lot more into the mix.
Spinach-artichoke.
They have great ingredients
in the sandwiches.
STOCKHOLM: Buffalo chicken.
All different kinds,
all different flavors.
STOCKHOLM: I'm up on a Pig Mac.
Pig Mac, it's actually my go-to.
Pig Mac.
Pig Mac --
pulled pork, mac and cheese
and bourbon caramelized onions
all inside
the grilled cheese sandwich.
You're a small food truck,
but you gettin'
all cheffy on it.
[ Laughs ]
This doesn't look like
the beginning of grilled cheese.
No, this is the rub
for our pork --
salt, brown sugar,
Sugar in the Raw,
white pepper,
espresso, cocoa powder,
cayenne pepper,
garlic powder,
little cinnamon,
and ground coriander seed,
ground cumin seed.
Next, we're gonna
rub the butt,
and we'll take it straight
to the smokers --
220-230,
10-12 hours overnight.
Butt's done?
We're just gonna pull it...
hit it with
apple cider vinegar.
ACV, man.
And then we make
an espresso barbecue sauce,
and then we reserve
some of the pork jus
from the drippings.
Barbecue rub.
Smells awesome.
Look at that.
I can't believe
that this sandwich
will be good at all
with that going in it.
We're gonna make
the cheese sauce
for the macaroni and cheese.
-That's the Mac of the Pig Mac.
Heavy cream, Béchamel,
all scratch-made.
Got it.
Garlic powder,
onion powder, mustard.
Got to have the mustard.
You need the tang.
Parmesan cheese,
cheddar cheese,
just make it nice and creamy.
Just a little bit of salt,
Aleppo pepper.
Little bit of a --
more of a fruitiness to it,
almost like
a cumin background.
Once the cheese
has melted,
we're just gonna
turn that flame off.
And in goes
the al dente pasta.
Just pour it out
to the sheet tray.
Let it congeal.
It'll tighten up.
And then you can
slam it together.
Then when it gets hot,
it will melt again.
That's exactly right.
I'm picking up
what you're laying down.
All right, first we're
just gonna butter our bread.
It's a little whipped
European butter.
Let's put some European
butter upon it.
Gonna add just a touch
of mayonnaise.
Keeps it from
penetrating the bread
so it doesn't
really get soggy.
Next down, we go
with our cheddar cheese,
our reserve macaroni and cheese,
cheddar cheese,
just a little salt,
little bit of fresh herbs.
Our caramelized bourbon onions,
we just cook these down,
deglaze them
at the very end
in just a little bit
of cola and bourbon,
our pulled pork,
and then just a little touch
of that espresso barbecue sauce.
♪♪
Did you just watch that?
That is the most organized,
professional setup
of a grilled cheese
I've ever seen.
Oh, fantastic.
Thank you.
I should have an ascot on.
[ Laughs ]
And then we will
lay it on the flat-top.
It's perfectly
golden brown,
It's got awesome
crunch texture to it.
Little finishing salt.
Of course.
[ Chuckling ]
And a little herbs.
Look at that.
Give me a moment.
That's ridiculous, dude.
Don't ever come here.
You will never be satisfied
with the grilled cheese
you make at home.
You know what,
I think it's awesome
'cause you get that
extra texture from the pasta.
The balance of the sandwich
is the key to it.
You got the right size bread
with the right crisp
with the right amount of cheese
with the right amount of pork
with the right amount
of seasoning.
Man, that is a platinum album
right there.
I can hear that playing
on the Flavortown station.
Here is your Pig Mac.
Awesome.
The meat is perfect.
The caramelized onions in there
just put it over the top,
I went on my first date
with my now-wife here.
The Pig Mac
sealed the deal.
The Pig Mac is what
made it happen.
This guy right here.
Best food truck in Charlotte.
FIERI:
And that's saying something.
The food truck scene
is very strong.
Every Friday,
there's a food-truck Friday.
This place
rates high, though?
Yes.
I eat here regularly.
MAN:
I tell you one thing,
it's not your standard
mother's grilled cheese.
We got a mushroom Gruyère.
I am eating
the mushroom and Gruyère.
With fresh mushrooms, it's
definitely one of my favorites.
Next, we are gonna
make the truffle spread
for the mushroom and Gruyère
grilled cheese.
We have Robiola cheese.
It's Italian.
It's like cream cheese
or a mascarpone.
It's just got
a little bit more flavor.
This is about as gourmet
of a grilled cheese truck
as I've ever seen
in my life.
Fresh chopped Rosemary,
fresh cracked pepper,
just a little bit
of lemon zest,
white truffle oil,
salt, and Aleppo pepper,
couple twists
of black pepper.
Yeah.
Next step.
We're going to sauté
cremini mushrooms,
shiitakes,
oyster mushrooms,
salt, and Aleppo,
just a little bit
of thyme,
a little bit more
of the whole butter.
We also have parsley
and sage.
Got it.
White wine.
Crack of black pepper,
a little bit of salt.
Brother, you're giving a lot
of respect to grilled cheese.
Absolutely.
So we're gonna build
our sandwich --
a little bit
of the butter spread.
European butter.
The Robiola spread,
Fontina for creaminess,
sliced Gruyère
and season that with salt,
herbs, mushrooms
will go right on there.
Flavor jets just turned on
in my mouth.
Straight to the grill.
Oh!
Mushrooms are gangster.
♪♪
Finishing salt, herbs.
[ Muffled ] Really?
[ Chuckles ]
It's about as close
to a grilled cheese
as I am to an astronaut.
This is like
a vegetarian beef Wellington.
The cheese kind of
replaces the meat,
the mushrooms
are fantastic,
the little kiss of the truffle,
the fresh herbs in it.
Little tomato soup
to dip it in?
Ohh! Stop.
I'm in France
right now.
Out of all the grilled cheese
I've ever had,
that's the peak.
And the soup --
dangerous.
I'm up on a mushroom Gruyère
and a Pig Mac.
Probably the cheesiest,
best grilled cheese
I've ever had in my life.
You can't be beat --
the mushrooms,
it's perfectly toasted.
Couple of my buddies
from Centerfold Agency.
This is like
grilled cheese...
On steroids.
I don't even know
if I can ever have
a regular
grilled cheese again.
Happiness on wheels.
Dude, you delivered.
Out of bounds.
Watch out for this guy.
So that wraps this edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
[ Muffled ]
Oh, you're still here?
See you next week.
[ Laughter ]