I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
I'm Guy Fieri,
...we're cruising the South...
It just keeps
sucking me back in.
...for some not-so-everyday
carnivore creations.
There is nothing that
I do not love about this.
Like in Charlotte...
Oh, yeah.
...a funky spot
adding Asian to Carolina 'cue.
I'm down with it
all day long.
Plus a burger joint
putting a twist on toppings.
Comes with a free
gym membership.
And in Kentucky...
I mean, this is just
flat-out comfort food.
...yep, it's food-coma central
at Louisville's first Irish pub.
I've had four bites.
And I'm already
getting glossy-eyed.
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
♪♪
In today's world,
you'd expect every major city
has every kind of restaurant --
Chinese, Mexican, Italian,
barbecue, even sushi.
But could you believe that,
before 1993,
here in Louisville, Kentucky,
they didn't have
an Irish pub and restaurant?
I mean, come on.
So I'm here in
the Crescent Hill neighborhood
to check out a joint
that's serving up
old-school real-deal recipes.
This is Irish Rover.
♪♪
WOMAN:
Bangers and mash.
This is the place to
get authentic Irish food.
Salmon gratin, cottage pie,
picking up, please.
So flavorful, you cannot
help but love it.
WOMAN:
Here's your fish and chips.
It's been open for over
20 years for a reason.
It's her father's fault.
-Your father's fault?
-Yes.
FIERI:
That's 'cause Ireland native
Michael Reidy
and his wife, Siobhan,
wouldn't have moved
from New York City
to her family home in Kentucky
without his fatherly advice.
He said, "You know, you need to
move here and open an Irish pub.
There is no Irish pub
here in Louisville."
I said, "Well, I'm only used
to being front of the bar."
He says, "Well, you better learn
to be behind the bar."
FIERI: So he did.
And for the last 20 years,
he's had local chef
Terrence Burbridge
putting the taste
of Michael's homeland
in front of their guests.
Plating up a stuffed cabbage.
Lamb-stuffed cabbage
is just to die for.
MAN: Minced lamb, vegetables,
spices, red wine,
and, uh, whiskey,
it just tastes good every time.
Terrence, are those
Celtic dreads?
I mean,
those are some dreads, dude.
How long you been
growing your hair?
24 years.
So, when you're hanging out
with people and they go,
"Dude, what do you do?"
I work at an Irish bar.
And they go,
"Yeah, okay, right."
-Yeah, yeah.
-"What do you really do?"
Oh, yeah.
Nobody believes it.
-What are we gonna make?
-Red-wine demiglace.
Let's do it.
Now, first,
what I'm gonna do is...
A little garlic down
into some olive oil.
A little bit of red onion,
red wine.
Then we're gonna add
a little beef base.
Water. Let that reduce down
for a little while.
Okay.
Strain the onions
and garlic out
and thicken it
with a cornstarch slurry.
And that will be the sauce
for the cabbage?
It's the sauce that goes
on the cabbage.
On top of the cabbage?
Got it.
And where
do these recipes come from?
Siobhan, Michael, myself.
There you go.
What are we making now?
This is the stuffing
for the cabbage?
It's the stuffing
for the cabbage.
Gonna add a little
ground lamb, celery, onion.
Green onion.
Red pepper, green bell pepper,
shallots.
I'm gonna add a little egg
for a binder, bread crumbs,
little white pepper,
little salt, some garlic,
red wine.
This is where things
are gonna get weird.
Why don't you pour
some whiskey?
Okay.
-About an ounce and a half.
-Oh.
After we're done,
we'll do that.
-That good?
-That's good.
And we'll mix it up,
add some cheddar cheese.
I got you.
So we got
the sweated cabbage leaves?
Yep.
Roll some of these up.
-That's it.
-Very easy.
And then I'm gonna add
some water to cover it
and some melted butter
on top.
Water and butter.
Aluminum foil in the oven
for an hour, 350.
-Okay. We good to go?
-I believe so.
You want me
to serve up the mash?
Yeah, beautiful.
-Oh, yeah.
-That's how it's done?
That's how it's done.
And this is one of
the big hits here?
Oh, yeah.
Here's our red-wine demi.
We're gonna garnish it
with some diced tomatoes,
a little bit of
chopped parsley.
And there's our
lamb-stuffed cabbage.
Mmm.
You come into an Irish place,
you're going to expect
that they're going to have
a stuffed cabbage
and it's gonna
be really good.
You guys did it right.
-Awesome.
-Everything's in balance.
You still get a little
bite out of the veggie.
Mm-hmm.
It hasn't cooked the lamb down
so far that it's dried out.
'Cause by no means
is it dry.
I thought the cheddar cheese
was a little bit weird,
and I can't even find
the cheddar cheese in here.
But there's something
going on.
Maybe that's keeping
some of the fat in there.
It works really well.
I would come back
and eat that every time.
Righteous.
Picking up
a stuffed cabbage.
It's really tasty,
and it works.
MAN: Just a really savory
comfort type of food.
You don't really find it
anywhere else around here.
Fish cakes
for table one, please.
Michael, being from
the west of Ireland,
he's brought back the taste,
the culture, the character,
and the look
of a real Ireland pub.
It's very festive here,
not party-like,
but just neighborhood-like.
Okay. So, the first time
I came to Louisville,
I ate
in this guy's steakhouse.
Now, he's got a steakhouse
in Cincinnati.
He's got one in Nashville.
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is the famous Jeff Ruby.
So you're in the first Irish pub
restaurant in Louisville.
You know what?
This is good, too.
-Stuffed cabbage.
-Very good.
You know how many people don't
make mashed potatoes right?
These are good.
FIERI: And the potatoes top off
this Irish staple.
When we come back,
we're gonna make some...
Cottage pie.
It's the ultimate comfort food.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hanging out at...
Irish Rover.
FIERI: The original Irish pub
and restaurant
in Louisville, Kentucky...
Hey, guys.
Have a Scotch egg for you.
...serving up food and culture
straight from the Emerald Isle.
What does the back
of the shirt mean?
-Beer, music, food, and fun.
-That's what I was gonna say.
You're gonna get a taste of
Ireland if you go to the Rover.
Cottage pie, picking up.
I love their cottage pie.
MAN: Guinness beef stew,
mashed potatoes,
cheesy goodness in a bread bowl,
stick to your ribs.
All right. What are we
making next, Chef?
Gonna make
Guinness beef stew,
which is the main component
in the cottage pie.
-First up...
-Little oil.
We're gonna add, uh,
5 pounds of premium beef.
-We're not seasoning the meat?
-No, not yet.
Okay. How long's
this gonna go, Chef?
-15 minutes.
-Brown it up.
Next step is gonna be?
Adding the carrots, celery.
No mirepoix, just carrots
and celery?
No onion.
-No onion?
-No onion.
What, you got a thing
against onion?
Uh, I got mad.
You got mad and said,
"That's it"?
No more onion.
-"We're done"?
-No more onion.
-Okay.
-Potatoes.
Peeled, chopped Russet
and a bunch of water.
Bunch of water to cover it.
-How long is this gonna go?
-40 minutes.
Uh, Chef, when are
we seasoning this?
After it comes to a boil.
It works.
-Trust me.
-I'm trusting you.
Then, we been boiling.
We're gonna add salt,
white pepper,
some bay leaf,
a little bit of beef base.
-Okay.
-Little bit of Guinness.
That's a lot of bit
of Guinness.
-Next up?
-Now I'm gonna thicken the stew.
We're gonna pour some of
the stew and strain it.
You're mining for gold
in Flavortown.
And then I'm gonna add
some roux to it.
Oil or butter
on that roux?
Butter, butter and flour.
-Thicken that up.
-Getting tight.
And then add it
back to the stew.
And how long is that gonna go
until we're ready to serve?
-Two or three minutes.
-And that's it.
-That's it.
-On to a big bread bowl.
Get you a good old bite
of it.
Now we're talking.
I'm definitely not
gonna make it home.
Top it off with
a little taters.
Cheddar makes it better.
And here you have
the cottage pie.
Oh, hi. I'm the surface
of the sun.
[ Laughs ]
-Hot.
-Just a little.
I was questioning
the seasoning timing.
But right off the bat,
you get that big old hit
of Guinness.
Right off the bat.
The richness really parlays
with the beef flavor
incredibly well.
The meat's
nice and tender.
Sourdough bread bowl.
That's a nice cheddar
on top of it.
I mean, this is just
flat-out comfort food.
I've had four bites.
And I'm already
getting glossy-eyed.
Yeah,
it's some good stuff.
It just keeps
sucking me back in.
Come get one more of it.
Like a tractor beam.
I just want one more.
You're a bad man.
-Cottage pie.
-Thank you.
Everything's delicious
about this dish.
It's tremendously hearty.
MAN:
I've had this in Ireland.
And this compares or beats
whatever I had there.
Salmon potato gratin.
Irish Rover is the best place.
Comfort food, friends, family.
It's just a fun place to come
any time of the year.
People tell me,
that have been in Ireland,
and when they come here, say,
"I think I'm still on vacation."
So that's as good
as it gets for me.
That's about as good as it works
for me.
Yes, sir.
-It's a great place.
-Thank you.
-Nice job.
-Appreciate it.
FIERI: Coming up
in Charlotte, North Carolina...
That's awesome.
...my country music buddy's
riding shotgun...
Own it.
Really get in there.
...to get a big bite out
of some bomb burgers.
Fantastic.
♪♪
So, I love coming
to Charlotte, North Carolina.
Let's go, dude.
I mean, the food's fantastic.
Got a bunch of buddies
that live here.
And they always say --
Come on, Matt. We got to go.
And they always say to me,
"Dude, when you go
to a 'Triple D' joint,
you got to bring me along."
So I got my country
singing buddy over here,
Matt Stillwell,
cranking up his new single.
Dude, this is
the best part.
♪ I still got your heart here
on my shoulder ♪
Aw, dude, you're right.
That is the best part.
And this is supposed
to be the best burger.
This is Bang Bang Burger.
Guacamole burger.
It's above and beyond
average here.
Hangover, table two.
Bold, uh, different.
FIERI: Which is the attitude
that classically trained chef
and New Yorker Joseph Huang
brought with him
when he moved to Charlotte
and opened this joint.
I'm very particular about
how we make the burgers.
The beef has to be really,
really good quality.
We get it from La Frieda
up in New York.
I'm used to that yummy,
beefy flavor of the burger.
Did you just use "yummy"?
Why don't you write a song
called "Bang Bang"?
Bang bang and yummy.
Mushroom and Swiss burger.
They've got a wide variety
of items
that you can put on the burger.
FIERI: From potato, bacon,
hash, and egg
to all kinds
of other crazy creations.
Burger bowl, table five.
And he's even rocking
a local favorite.
Pimiento burger.
MAN:
I'm having the pimiento burger.
It's got the pimiento cheese
with fried pickles.
It's a Southern classic.
Let's talk about
pimiento cheese.
Pimiento cheese
is yummy.
Everybody at home,
just so you know,
we're gonna count how many times
he says "yummy."
So we're at four right now.
So I'm starting out
with some mayonnaise on here.
I'm gonna put a little bit
of Monterey Jack cheese,
shredded American, and then
some shredded Swiss cheese.
Why the three
different cheeses?
Tastes good together,
not yummy.
Diced jalapeños here,
pimiento.
-Okay.
-A little bit of sriracha.
My mammy and gramps
are from North Carolina.
And when she made
pimiento cheese,
I don't remember
the sriracha being in there.
You grew up in the hill country
of North Carolina.
-Sriracha?
-Not at all.
And then this is a mix
of salt and pepper.
What's the name
of your new album?
"Yummy Bang Bang
Country Music."
-Country and western.
-And western.
That's awesome.
Now, this gets better when it
spends a little time together?
Yeah, it gets
a little bit more dense.
Fantastic.
So we're gonna go ahead and make
the brine for our pickles.
We have some hot water
starting right here,
garlic cloves,
whole jalapeños.
Jalapeño.
Brown sugar,
regular sugar,
some kosher salt,
peppercorns.
So now it has to cook
for 10 minutes.
We're gonna go ahead
and add our white vinegar,
some apple cider vinegar.
All right. So we're gonna
let this sit here.
Cook it down
a little bit.
You know, the flavors
actually come out.
And then this is gonna go over
the top of the sliced cucumbers.
And how long are you
gonna let it brine?
Usually two, three days.
How are they gonna
be served on the burger?
We're gonna go ahead and dip
in some tempura batter.
We're gonna fry them,
get 'em a little crispy.
What do those taste like?
Yummy.
All right,
now we're gonna go ahead
and cook our
pimiento cheeseburger.
Kosher salt and pepper.
We get a great bun
from the local bakery
called Duke's Bread.
They're yummy.
They're delicious.
Add our homemade
pimiento cheese.
Got that right here.
And then we garnish
with our crispy, fried pickles.
-That's all she wrote, huh?
-Yeah.
You know how to do this?
Own it.
-Really get in there.
-Yeah, man.
Great burger.
The La Frieda meat
definitely is a plus-plus.
Get a lot of beef flavor,
lot of pimiento.
I think that that yummy pimiento
cheese on this is...
It doesn't count
if you say it.
-...is awesome.
-Really nice bun.
And I think that the fried
pickle is the kicker.
-That's what makes it work.
-It's good.
-Tasty pickle.
-They're yummy.
That's eight.
Those that are
playing along at home,
total data board,
we're at eight, going for 12th.
The pimiento burger is great.
It's got good flavor.
It's some of the best
pimiento cheese I've ever had.
The deep-fried pickles
give it a crunch.
And you have the little
kick of the spices.
One ingredient doesn't
overpower the other.
-Nice.
-That's kind of like in music.
Well said.
You don't want
too much cowbell.
-No.
-Awesome.
Favorite burger
on the menu?
I really love
the Soul Burger.
-Gangnam Style.
-I got a burger bowl.
-You ordered the Cowboy Burger?
-Mm-hmm.
MAN:
I'm a barbecue-sauce man.
Me and you both.
Today, I had the Fried
Sweet Potato Brie Burger.
It's got the Brie
with sweet potatoes.
The maple-cranberry sauce on top
really ties it all together.
All right, Chef,
what are we into?
Maple-cranberry cream.
We've got sour cream,
mayonnaise.
Comes with a free
gym membership.
-Yeah.
-This is real maple syrup.
-B or A?
-B.
B has more flavor.
Dry cranberries.
So I'm gonna go ahead and
blend this until it's smooth.
I've seen some weird sauces
on burgers, Chef.
-Could take the cake.
-It's gonna be good.
I didn't think
that was going to be good.
-Yeah?
-That's really good.
Now, these are
the sweet-potato balls --
roasted sweet potatoes,
melted butter, maple syrup,
diced prosciutto, chives.
Go ahead and mix this up
by hand and scoop it out.
Put it in some tempura batter
and some bread crumbs
and drop it in the fryer.
-Okay. Let's make this burger.
-All right.
These are burgers
that we just grilled.
And there's Brie cheese
on top of that.
A little sauce.
Now, these are
the sweet-potato balls.
-That doesn't suck.
-That's good.
A little bit of arugula.
Here we go.
-Oh, yeah.
-Mm-hmm.
-That's a pretty mature burger.
-Yeah, that's good.
I don't want
to downplay the meat
'cause the meat's really good.
But it's the sweet-potato ball
is the kicker.
Adds a little
texture to it, right?
The burger is exactly
how it should be.
That's why
that stands out.
Let's do this again.
Enjoy.
I have a Fried Sweet Potato
and Brie Burger.
It's just fun, almost like
Thanksgiving dinner party.
The sweet potato really, uh,
complements the Brie.
And it's outstanding.
If there was a word
that you would describe it
that started with a "Y"...
Yummy.
Oh, boy.
I'm giving this place a 10.
The creativity that goes into
every burger really shows.
Nice job, Chef.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Up next, we're staying
in Charlotte...
That's really good.
...for a Far East, Down South
taco-charcuterie-barbecue
mash-up.
Did you catch all that?
You get a complimentary
feed bag to put on?
You know we're
a true friendship
when we start
cleaning each other.
We're trying to have a moment
over here
if you could keep it noisy.
♪♪
So I'm here in the Cotswold
neighborhood
of Charlotte, North Carolina,
in a strip mall
to check out a barbecue joint.
You never heard that one
coming before, have you?
Well, it's not just
any barbecue joint.
No, this one's got kind of,
like, a funky Asian fusion.
Well, I guess that's why
they call it The Improper Pig.
-Cotswold Burger.
-The food here is incredible.
Korean barbecue salmon up.
The most unique barbecue
place they'll ever eat at.
FIERI:
'Cause while Chef Darius Amidi's
bringing the bark,
owner Will Bigham's adding
Asian flavor
held over from the joint
he ran here before.
It's just really
kind of a combination
you normally don't get.
FIERI:
From wok-seared green beans
and Southern-inspired egg rolls
to this meaty mash-up.
Chaobao Taco up.
The Chaobao Tacos are wonderful.
And all the flavors together
are just so delicious.
FIERI:
Give me the breakdown here.
Well, we're gonna start
with Will's Rub.
It's called Will's Rub?
It's called Will's Rub.
Will actually made it.
-No, really.
-Yep.
So we have ground
celery seed, paprika,
chili powder, cumin,
brown mustard.
-Cayenne?
-Yes, sir.
Add, uh, ground oregano,
garlic powder.
-Onion powder.
-Little bit of brown sugar.
-That's light brown.
-Think it's a Southern thing.
Some course ground
black pepper, kosher salt.
Mix that all together,
onto the pork butt.
Boneless butt.
I like the way you rub.
Roll.
You know what I meant.
-We let it sit for 24 hours.
-Okay.
Then we'll smoke it
with hickory wood 12 hours, 220,
till it hits
about 190 degrees.
All right, Chef,
what are we into?
Sesame-ginger dressing
for our Asian coleslaw.
So start with water.
That's always
my favorite ingredient.
Japanese vinegar,
soy sauce.
Tons of ginger.
Black pepper,
brown ginger.
We're gonna put
our miso paste in.
Miso paste in
a barbecue joint?
We're gonna get run out of town,
buddy, if you keep this up.
Honey, dried, fried onions,
roasted, dried garlic.
After that, we're gonna
Bermix this.
I'm gonna slowly
add sesame oil,
a little bit of, uh,
blended oil.
Better get union
scale for that.
Oh, take some of that.
So our Asian slaw's
Napa cabbage,
carrots in it,
fresh chopped "cilantra."
-What did you say?
-Cilantro.
Play that tape back.
"Cilantra."
He said, "cilantra,"
didn't he?
Scallions,
or the "scal-yons."
Ginger dressing.
Look at all the ginger
sitting in there,
that pulpy-ness.
Oh, that's awesome.
I could eat the whole thing.
Next step, we're gonna
pull some pork.
What is that, kind of like
the discount Wolverine?
That is
a discount Wolverine.
The bark on this is gangster.
Nice and tender.
This is gonna go
together for the bun?
We're actually gonna do this
in the, uh -- in the wok.
Okay. Wok out.
Just a good old chunk
of pork in there,
spicy hoisin sauce,
steamed bun.
-Where are we getting the buns?
-We have a little Asian shop.
-Makes buns for you?
-And they make our buns.
Gonna drizzle the hoisin on top
and the Asian slaw.
Oh, that's good. The pick is
gonna really do something.
I tried the bamboo umbrellas.
They didn't work.
Yeah, that's ridiculous.
There is nothing that
I do not love about this.
That's really good.
Is there a little spice
in your hoisin?
It is. It's, uh, roasted,
uh, manzano peppers.
Thanks, uh,
for letting me know.
The spicy hoisin
is gangster.
That's my favorite part
of the whole thing.
The slaw is spot-on,
the pork butt super tender,
and a really good bun.
For something like that
to have that much flavor
to give me
that kind of punch,
I'm down with it
all day long.
-Fantastic, Chef.
-Thank you.
I love the Chaobao Taco.
Has some ginger accents,
which I really love.
That whole combination
really works good together.
FIERI: But just because they're
mixing in some Far East
doesn't mean they've forgotten
their Southern roots
'cause when it comes to 'cue,
they got you covered.
We have six
different sauces,
everything made
from scratch in-house.
WOMAN:
You can try something spicy
or if you want something
kind of mild and comforting.
FIERI:
And they all come standard
with this smoked meat sampler.
Improper Charcuterie up.
It's got ribs, smoked sausage,
pulled pork, and the brisket.
It's awesome.
All right, Chef,
so what are we into now?
-We're gonna rub our ribs.
-So St. Louis-style.
And, uh, the rub we already
made earlier, Will's Rub.
Got it. Will's Rub.
Will there be enough?
There will be plenty.
And with the brisket over here,
this monstrosity
[Whistles] I guess that's where
all the dinosaurs ended up.
Let 'em go for 24 hours,
then in the smoker.
It's about 12 hours
to 13 hours.
-Okay. At 220?
-220.
Put it together, boss.
House-made slaw,
pickled onions, pimiento cheese.
We've got our grilled
andouille sausage, ribs.
-Okay.
-Pulled pork,
followed up by
the slow-cooked brisket.
And then we finish it
with house chips.
Do you get a complimentary
feed bag to put on or...
It'll definitely
fill you up.
Good-looking rib.
Look at that.
Some good smoke,
nice bark.
You finish those
on the grill?
Yes, sir.
Here's a little piece
of that brisket.
Tender, a lot of smoke inside.
Pimiento's nice.
Dip the chip,
the whole thing.
When it comes
to this cornucopia,
what's the Queen Bee?
Queen Bee is our, uh,
house-made sweet sauce.
That definitely works.
Eastern Vinegar,
this is all Carolina.
This is what it's really
all about for me.
Oh, yeah. And you cooked
all the meats correctly.
I mean, everything's
done the right way.
But to give people
the chance
to take it the next step
their way
is, uh -- is pretty
smart business.
That's really good.
-Well done, Chef.
-Thank you.
MAN: Awesome barbecue ribs,
the brisket,
just the right amount of fat.
And then the sauces
are phenomenal.
The Improper Pig is wonderful.
When you come in here,
everything's a treat.
Well done, man.
They're lucky to have you.
Thank you.
You did good,
you and your "cilantra."
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
-Favorite thing on the menu?
-Oh, the ice-cream sandwiches.
What? I'm over here
talking to you about barbecue.
And you give me
ice-cream sandwich?
I have a dessert problem.
Actually, this is not
even really a food show.
We're here to talk
to you about it.
You were actually scared
for a second.