I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out
for a special edition
of "Triple D"
in Barcelona, Spain.
That's right.
I've crossed the Atlantic...
I'm in Spain.
...to belly up
to Barcelona's food scene...
Get ready.
...loaded with dishes
we're not seeing every day
in the States.
Look at you,
starting to sweat!
Like Spanish sausage
sandwiches...
Perfect.
...outrageous octopus...
It's, like, the most tender
lobster you'll ever try.
...righteous rabbit...
That's got to be in the top
three rabbit I've ever had.
...and even a big ol'
bowlful of snails.
Whoa!
We're right into it.
We're not even gonna
talk about it.
So grab your one-way ticket...
This is no joke.
I'm not kidding you.
...to this international
flavor fest.
That's not even good.
It's outstanding.
It's all right here,
right now on "Triple D"
in Barcelona!
So I'm here in Barcelona, Spain,
in the famous
St. Jaume Square.
That's City Hall.
Now, there's places to eat.
But how do you
pick the right one?
How 'bout a joint from 1951?
Still in the family,
this is Can Conesa.
Yeah, it's so good.
Why is this place
so good?
So you've been coming to this
since you were a little kid.
Really?
FIERI: Well, it looks like
I came to the right place,
which was started by
Pedro Conesa 64 years ago.
Now this joint's on its
second generation with son Josep
and his wife, Marta,
running the show.
Who's gonna cook?
[ Speaks Spanish ]
You do the sauce,
he does the cooking.
FIERI: I guess that's the way
it's got to be in a tiny place
turning and burning
all kinds of sandwiches...
...with the regional
Catalonia pork sausage
playing heavy here.
Today, I'm having a Carn
D'olla sandwich with sausages.
And it has a sauce
that tastes really good.
How do you say sandwich?
Bocadillo?
-El bocadillo.
-Bocadillo.
Okay. I'm ready.
This cooks?
It [whistles]
This is like
late-night TV.
-Onions...
-Caramelized onions.
-...with wine.
-The white wine.
Oh, hey, hey, hey.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
No? Okay.
I'm in Spain.
Okay.
-Oil.
Beef stock.
I've never seen a blender
that cooks, ever.
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
-Paprika?
And that's it.
Now
this is gonna get hot.
18 1/2 minutes,
and it's gonna cook
this sauce down.
I've seen it all.
Okay, Josep.
Let's make sandwiches.
So the sausage is...
-Carn D'olla.
Okay.
Not your average panini press,
let me tell you that.
It is smoking hot.
This is no joke.
I'm not kidding you.
So we grill the sausage,
caramelized onions...
I've seen a lot of panini
presses in my life.
I've never seen
one that hot.
Look what it did
to the sausage right there.
Okay.
I'm so hungry.
And that's how you do it.
Look at this.
Simple, to the point,
made fresh, hot and fast.
Just huge texture
coming off of that
'cause that press is,
like, 9,000...
[ Speaks Spanish ]
-Celsius?
-Celsius.
Surface of the sun.
Fantastic.
The onions
are great in it.
The sausage itself,
got a lot of flavor.
The texture of the bread
is dynamite,
like this multigrain
baguette
that it comes with.
-Bocadillo Carn D'olla.
Delicious.
Little kitchen,
big menu, crazy.
You can eat all
the sandwiches gluten-free.
So everything here
in the land of tradition
can be made gluten-free?
-Exactly.
Is there a big movement
in Spain for gluten-free?
Yeah.
FIERI: But no matter
how they make 'em,
these sandwiches are all
about Old-World flavor.
Catalan being
the part of Spain
where another sausage
specialty involves
what they call calcots...
...which finds its way into the
Botifarra de Calcots sandwich.
Romesco.
Oh, I know Romesco!
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Caramelizada.
What does that mean?
Caramelized!
Oil.
Ooh!
-Is it? Sí or no?
-Sí!
-Ah!
-Almendras.
-Almonds.
-Garlic.
-Oh, garlic.
Sal.
-Paprika?
-Paprika.
-Vino?
-Oh, sí!
Oh, yeah, yeah! It's vinegar.
Watch out for her.
-Free-gluten.
-Free-gluten pan?
Poco.
Oh!
-Good?
-Fantastic!
Good little nuttiness,
a little bit of spice to it,
nice and creamy,
perfect!
And what's that go on?
-Calcots.
In Catalan, they take
these calcots, these onions,
and they dip 'em
in the Romesco and eat 'em.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
So we cut up the onions
and the onions
are inside of the sausage.
Again, we go into this screaming
450-degree panini oven.
Look at that -- nice crust
to it right off the bat.
Now the sausage,
the caramelized onions again.
Romesco.
You get the moisture
and the flavor that,
a lot of times,
people use mayonnaise.
I just can't believe how fast
they make their sandwiches.
[ Whistles ]
Not hot or anything.
Here we go.
-Hot, eh?
-Uh-huh.
The Romesco...
-Okay?
It's okay?
It's perfecto!
Really good bread,
really nice crust to it.
The caramelized onions work
as a fantastic foundation.
Really good sausage,
that green onion inside...
I'm getting a little fennel
seed out of this, not spicy,
but just tons of flavor.
Dynamite.
The onions and the texture
of the sausage are really tasty.
It's a better. It's
a better. It's a best.
MAN:
And it's a perfect place
to eat a great sandwich
in Barcelona.
So that's it.
So here's our first location
on "Triple D"
here in Barcelona.
And I didn't expect
to find this
in the middle
of a very famous square.
You continue
to do business
as if you were only
serving local people.
And that's the reason
that I'm here.
Gracias.
He's got it right.
I can't wait to see
what the rest of the trip's
gonna be like.
Let's go.
FIERI: Coming up, I'm bringing
along some backup...
Ladies, ladies, ladies,
gentlemen, gentlemen,
gentlemen...
...for some real-deal
regional recipes...
Unbelievable. In essence,
it's Spanish soul food.
...including one I'll always
grab off the menu.
That's all octopus
all day.
Where are you?
Ahh!
I always have
friends saying to me,
"Listen, man, when you go
to someplace really cool,
you got to bring me along."
So here I am.
Marcel Reece,
pro ball player,
and we are
in Barcelona, Spain.
What do you think?
-Not too bad.
You come to Barcelona,
there's one thing
you got to try.
And I know he doesn't like it.
And that's pulpo.
Pulpo, as in octopus?
No place better
than Pulperia A Gudiña.
This has got a lovely
authentic feel to it.
The food is fantastic.
Bueno. Señora.
You can either get a small,
like, appetizer
or it could even be
your whole meal.
FIERI: What is Galicia?
Which is the birthplace
of Jose Luis Sierra,
who opened this joint
back in the '90s
with fellow food-biz vet,
Andres Flores.
And they're cranking out these
dishes Galicia is known for.
Galician style is simple dishes,
a lot of seafood prepared
in the old style?
Like potatoes served up
with one of my favorites,
pulpo, you know, octopus.
The first time he's gonna
try octopus, the pulpo.
Look at you,
starting to sweat!
-It's all octopus.
-That's all octopus all day.
No agua caliente, fria!
Cold water,
just washing it off.
And he just
didn't drop it in.
He tempered it a little bit
so it didn't seize up so fast.
Why the copper pot?
The pot special?
Got it.
Un hora?
[ Speaks Spanish ]
So 35, 40 minutes.
Bring it out.
Go ahead, Marcel.
Jump in there.
Don't drop it.
-Pour off the water.
That's not hot at all.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
This is your new
kitchen assistant?
It's great. I think
it's a good idea.
Not bad, huh?
Trim up that octopus quite nice.
This is how you
do it in Galicia.
That's one serving.
Decent portion, okay?
Paprika.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
He's got smoked paprika
and the sweet paprika in there.
Beautiful.
There we go.
Fantastic.
Ladies, ladies, ladies,
gentlemen, gentlemen,
gentlemen...
You're going for it,
going big.
Ah! It's good?
Almost a, uh,
crab-like texture.
It's, like, the best,
most tender lobster
you'll ever try.
There's a little bit
of texture to it.
What I like is the spicy
and the sweet of the paprika.
He uses a really
nice grainy salt
and that really
strong olive oil.
-That's awesome.
-Oh, dynamite.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
The octopus here
is very good.
-Have you tried octopus?
-I've never.
-We haven't had it yet.
-Everybody has to jump in.
Here we go.
Not bad, huh?
Not bad.
WOMAN:
I love the food here.
And I feel like
the little plates are awesome,
being able to share
and try everything.
You can stick
to the basics,
but you got to venture
out a little bit, right?
Which means digging into
this joint's
grilled razor clams,
Iberian cold cuts
and traditional comfort food.
Okay, what's next?
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Galician soup?
I think he said, uh,
"I'd like you to stick around
and do the dishes later."
This is just
a salted piece of ham.
So you got to soak it
a little bit
to start leeching out
some of that salt.
Otherwise, it's gonna
be salt city.
This is gonna go
in to make the stock.
Cabbage, the potatoes, chorizo,
and that's
Spanish-style chorizo.
He pokes it 'cause it's got
the casing around it.
So as it cooks in there,
it leeches out
a little bit of that flavor.
So the beans...
[ Speaks Spanish ]
...paprika and garlic oil.
Veinte minutos?
-No. Mas.
Mas?
Un hora?
Hour and a half to 2 hours.
Fantastic.
Try not to
burn yourself.
Mm, that is hot.
Hot, caliente!
-Muy caliente.
-Where's the chorizo?
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
So it just cooks
with the chorizo.
That flavors the pot,
but you take the chorizo
out for another --
for another tapas.
A great ham-flavored stock.
The beans kind of break
down a little bit.
And that's what kind of
gives it a little viscosity.
And I like the way the cabbage
is all broken down.
Awesome soup.
-I think the best part is
when you get one
of those potatoes,
soaks up all the flavor.
-Yeah.
The seasoning from the --
from the chorizo.
That's a lot of flavor.
In essence,
it's Spanish soul food.
Bueno?
-Delicious.
-Unbelievable.
Thank you.
-I mean, simple --
simple dish but,
gosh, it's good.
I love the soup.
It's wonderful.
What can you say about it?
It's just a --
a great place to eat.
I think you got
a real good example
of a type of Spanish food,
simple food made
correctly by good people.
I can really appreciate
the care and love,
passion you can see
and taste in the food.
-Gracias.
Thank you, appreciate it.
FIERI: Up next, we're hitting
more Spanish specialties...
Whoa,
just serving it up.
...at a fantastic family joint.
This is the idea
of your grandmother's.
Yes.
...cooking up
comfort Catalan-style.
I love rabbit liver.
So I'm here smack-dab
in the middle of Barcelona
in an area known as Gracia.
And I'm looking for
a mom-and-pop joint
that opened in 1986.
And everybody says,
"You got to come check it out.
And, particularly,
you got to try the snails."
Snails wasn't exactly
the tapas I was thinking of.
But I'm game.
This is Cal Boter.
[ Man speaks Spanish ]
There's no other
place like this.
[ Woman speaks Spanish ]
FIERI: Highlighting both
the cuisine of Catalonia,
which is the northeastern
region of Spain,
and the family recipes
of Encarna Navarro.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Yeah, you so wanted
to make a restaurant
that was like your home.
And you and your husband
started the restaurant.
Yes.
And though her husband,
Tony, has passed away,
she and their kids,
including son Pau Boté,
still keep
the original spirit alive.
You're gonna eat very good.
FIERI: Thanks in large part
to Chef Guido Donatelli,
who's been here
for over a decade,
cooking up the local
Catalan classics.
[ Man speaks Spanish ]
Have you ever had
snails before?
-Yeah.
-How are these?
It's super good, yeah.
I remember the first time
I try it, I feel like,
"Oh, my God.
How can I live before?"
Okay.
What are we making?
We're gonna make snails.
Just so you know,
I've eaten a lot of escargot
when I lived in France.
I don't think that
I've ever prepared them.
Whoa!
We're right into it.
We didn't even -- we're not
even gonna talk about it.
You boil it.
It's for cleaning the snails.
-This is for cleaning them.
-Yes.
Lot of people
eat the snails?
Yes. The day for the snails
normally is Sunday.
The day for the snails.
Then we're gonna
rinse them.
I'm psyching myself up.
These are gonna be awesome.
BOTé:
Now, for second time...
We're gonna cook them again,
but that water will be seasoned.
-Exactly.
-Chile de arbol.
Salt.
Herbes de Provence
and thyme?
Yes.
-And how long?
-10 minutes.
And then
do we have a sauce?
For the sauce,
you put oil, onion...
Green bell pepper?
-Yes.
-Okay.
-And we wait a little bit.
-We wait.
'Cause it's snail day.
We put, uh, garlic.
It's, uh, white wine.
-Okay.
-And we wait.
We love wait
for the snails.
We love to wait for the snails.
Ah, me, too.
Okay.
-Tomillo.
-More thyme?
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
-The Herbes de Provence,
hot pepper,
the bay leaf and more chile.
I mean, if you can't like
snails with this sauce,
you should, well,
not eat snails.
Okay. And then we put
the snails in the sauce?
-Yes.
-That's a lot of snails.
Chicken stock.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Garlic.
A little garlic
and some nuts.
This'll thicken this up
a little bit.
-10 minutes more.
-I'm getting ready.
I hope everybody at home
in Flavortown is
appreciating the...
Oh-ho, just serving it up,
the whole bounty there.
Okay,
so how do you do it?
Okay.
-Take it.
Fantastic, super tender,
not chewy at all.
There's good spice
from the chorizo.
The broth itself
is dynamite.
I mean, it's a lot
of big flavor.
Mm.
This is outstanding!
I mean, come on.
I don't like snails.
But you come and have this,
you will not forget it.
Nice job, my friends.
-Okay.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
The mix of all
the flavors, it's perfect.
So this is my buddy,
Vincenzo.
And he worked at a place
called A Casa Mia
in Majorca, Spain,
where Hunter and I shot
the European vacation.
The paella was
off the charts.
So he came over
to visit.
I put snails
in front of him.
What do you think?
-I think it's amazing.
Fantastic.
-It is fantastic.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
MAN:
It's such a great restaurant.
It's really nice place
to gather with, um, friends
and have a really good time.
This feels like
the kind of house
that you throw
a party in.
It has that energy.
FIERI: Which is part of
Encarna's husband's legacy.
Your father,
did he cook?
He preferred to, uh...
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
-He'd prefer to eat.
He'd invite all the people
to my house and say,
"My wife is gonna cook
for all of you."
Yes.
FIERI: These days,
Encarna spends
most of her time baking.
But the kitchen's rocking
with their family favorites.
To round it out,
we're gonna have
some rabbit cooked in gravy
that's made with
the rabbit liver.
Exactly.
Mm.
So you can't miss this one.
I have a feeling it
just might surprise us all
when we come back.
Welcome back. We're hanging
out in Barcelona, Spain,
at Cal Boter.
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
How do you describe
this restaurant to people?
Original Catalan food.
Which is home-cooked
comfort food like stews,
seafood and meats
that are rare in the U.S.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Rabbit is a traditional plate
here in Catalonia.
You cook it in the right way,
it's one of the best meats
that you will ever eat.
Okay.
So we got half a rabbit.
BOTé: And we bind with,
uh...
Herb-infused oil.
And we put
salt and pepper.
And we put in the grill.
-We're gonna make the sauce.
-Exactly.
-Okay.
We have oil.
Pepper, bay leaf,
laurel, parsley.
What is that, liver?
-Yes.
I love rabbit liver.
Okay, we cook that.
And then we hit
the chicken stock.
Sí. Water.
This is
a traditional sauce?
It's a traditional sauce
from my grandmother.
Now we wait 10 minutes
for boil it.
-Cook it.
-And then after, we mix it.
They can't blend
those rabbit livers enough.
And now the rabbit.
That's getting it done.
-And now we put inside.
-In the sauce.
I love what he's done
with the color.
That's not even good.
It's outstanding!
That sauce is, like,
the best comfort gravy
your grandma makes.
Yeah.
Nice and luxurious
and rich.
Mm.
The rabbit's tender.
It has great flavor,
a little bit of grill
on it, great.
But there's no texture
in the sauce.
That's got to be in the top
three best rabbit
I've ever had.
[ Man speaks Spanish ]
It's so good.
The liver sauce in the rabbit,
I don't have
any words to --
to describe this flavor.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
MAN: Cal Boter is
the restaurant
to go if you come here,
to Spain,
just to eat
these amazing dishes.
This has really made it
a well-rounded tour
for "Triple D"
in Barcelona, Spain.
It just shows you
the wide variety
and creativity that there
is in Spanish cooking.
You got to come visit
this joint, for sure.
One more rabbit.
So that's it for this
special edition
of "Triple D" in Barcelona.
But don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over the place.
And I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
You know
the chicken dance?
[ Both humming "Chicken Dance" ]
[ Laughter ]
There you go!