I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
-Hit it.
-Bam!
...we're grabbing
a little ice...
I'm going to need this in, like
a big, Styrofoam trucker mug.
There you go.
...and a whole lot of spice...
Nice big hit of that
up there, yeah.
...like in
Cathedral City, California...
Yeah, that'll do.
...where sandwiches should come
with a smoke alarm...
Now we're warming up.
Here we go.
...and at a Maui spot...
I don't know if I should eat it
or take a picture of it, huh?
...mixing Southern hearty
with island party.
It's like you're working
at the carnival,
like you run the Zipper
or something.
Plus, a taste of New York
in Norfolk...
Dude, you run, like,
the biggest wing emporium.
...where things are heating up
in more ways than one.
Aah!
He's an animal!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Norfolk, Virginia.
Now, a lot of folks
may not know this,
but this is home to the largest
naval base in the world.
A big thank you to all
the sailors and their families
that support our great country.
So, you got all these
fantastic men and women
and all the people
that it takes to support them.
So what does that get you?
It gets a lot of great
restaurants,
like the one
in the big blue building.
This is the Dirty Buffalo.
All right, I got
12 bone-in wings.
The wings are
absolutely the best
of any place I've had, anywhere.
When I walk in here, I feel
like I'm in Buffalo, New York.
I got a dirty bird for you.
WOMAN: Russ has done
a really good job
marrying two of the things
that mean the most to him --
his roots in upstate New York
and going to school
at Old Dominion.
FIERI: Which means
Rochester native Russell Gilbert
is combining his Virginia
marketing degree with love
for his hometown classics.
Dude, you run, like,
the biggest wing emporium
in the Eastern scene.
I mean, south of Buffalo,
you're it.
Yeah.
And with a new sauce
creation every week,
you got to know
his catalog runs deep.
From the mildest to sweet
to very spicy.
I got 12 wings, Buffalo Soldier.
I'm a new member of
the Buffalo Soldier brigade.
Do you get a T-shirt for that,
or do get to...?
I'm wondering.
It's his take on Jamaican jerk
barbecue sauce,
and it's really delicious.
All right, let's get into it.
What are we making?
Buffalo Soldier sauce
for our wings.
We're going to sauté
the habanero peppers,
and then I'm going to add
some minced garlic.
And then we're just going
to take tomatoes, green onions.
Then I'll just add the peppers
and minced garlic in there.
Bet a nice big hit
of that will clear you out.
I take the seeds out
so it's not too bad.
Then just in the pot,
hot sauce, melted butter,
some lime juice, soy sauce.
The kid from Rochester
just added soy sauce?
Dude, you sound
like my dad.
Dude, it's good!
I'm off the walls.
I don't even know
what that just was.
All right,
all right, all right.
And then we're going to add
some apple cider vinegar,
brown sugar,
Jamaican jerk spice,
ground thyme,
ground allspice,
minced ginger,
some salt and pepper.
And here's
our pureed veggies.
We're just going to
bring it up to a boil.
And let it reduce,
and that's it.
Boom!
There you go. There you go!
Talk to me about the type
of wing we're using.
They're fresh, never frozen.
As big as I can get the wings,
I'll get them.
Like Pterodactyl.
Yeah!
What type of oil?
As best an oil as I can get.
The oil in the fryer should look
like that. I'm impressed.
What temperature we cooking
the wings at?
350, about 16 minutes.
So, we got our 12 wings
ready to go.
I pride myself
as a wing aficionado.
I mean, if I'm not getting funk
and crunch, I'm a walking.
Dude, I'll take that challenge
all day of the week.
This I'm liking.
You got to paint it.
'Cause if the wings
are cooked right,
they're still absorbing
the sauce
as they sit there
in the basket.
♪♪
I will tell you this.
The non-frozen wing
reigns supreme.
To be really honest with you,
I don't see it hardly anywhere.
The wings are tender.
There's a lot of flavor.
We got great crust.
Sauce is so good I want
to use it as a stir-fry sauce.
Yeah.
That's a tasty basket
of wings, my friend.
Almost as good
as the dance moves.
Hit it!
Bam!
Come on!
-12-piece Buffalo Soldier.
-There's a nice heat to it,
but it also has this tropical
feel like Jamaican jerk.
A lot of flavor
and pretty complex.
They do a good job
serving multiple wings
and all kinds of beer.
FIERI: Which, of course,
goes great with football.
Every Sunday, it's packed
in here with Bills' fans.
FIERI: And sometimes,
even former Bills players
like Hall-of-Famer Bruce Smith.
First-round draft pick
in 1985.
The man that has 200
quarterback sacks, 11 Pro Bowls.
How's Russ doing down here
with Dirty Buffalo?
SMITH: He's legit.
If you want a buffalo chicken
wing, go to Buffalo
or you got to come here.
And the Northeast feast
just keeps on coming.
So, in upstate New York,
they have what's called
the garbage plate.
Russ brought it down here, added
his own special recipe to it.
I got a dirty chick,
Cajun buffalo.
Something you would never think
to put together with hash browns
and the mac n' cheese,
and then the chicken.
-What are we making first?
-It's the sauce first.
-Okay.
-So, we're going to take
some hot sauce,
heat it up to a boil.
Take some melted butter,
orange juice.
Come on down
to Russ' Diet Barn.
Ketchup, some brown sugar,
a little bit of water,
granulated sugar,
apple cider vinegar,
some dry mustard,
yellow mustard, honey,
and some barbecue sauce.
Some Cajun seasoning.
Mix this all up.
Let it reduce.
Yep.
Boom, boom, boom!
Aah!
He's an animal!
Now we're going to dredge
the chicken tenders.
Pop it in the fryer.
Now we're going to
make a mac n' cheese.
We're going to make
our cheese sauce --
heavy cream in first, salt,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion,
white pepper.
And then we'll just
whisk that in really good,
and then bring it up
to a boil.
Now the American?
Yep.
That's a lot
of American cheese.
Sharp cheddar.
Slowly add the cheese.
Don't go want to go too fast
with the melting
or it'll clump up.
We're just going to add a little
bit of water to the skillet,
throw the pasta in
that's already been cooked.
Then we're just going
to add cheese sauce.
Mac 'n cheese
is ready to go?
Yep.
Take our home fries,
put the mac n' cheese
on top of there.
Take our chicken tenders,
add our Cajun buffalo to it.
Does Bruce Smith eat this
when he comes in?
Dude, he eats
a lot of wings.
Paint it up.
That's the dirty chick.
I mean, I think the challenge
is, is can you cut into it
without having it all
go shoot off the plate.
Hence the dirty plate.
That's a really good
tender.
It's got
a great breading to it.
Yep.
You got to have somebody
in the treadmill business.
Put on some pounds
and then take them away.
Nicely done.
We got a Cajun buffalo
dirty chick for you, sir.
The Cajun buffalo's
my favorite sauce.
It's really spicy
and thick and great.
I could eat this
three meals a day.
There's a reason why
this is a locals' favorite.
It's the kind of place
everybody's
going to want
to have in their town.
You got a lot of creativity.
Your enthusiastic.
Bam!
There you go.
Adios.
FIERI: Next up, things
are going South in Maui...
You guys
will dig this.
...at a joint where
some Georgia boys
are laying it on thick.
It's a monster, bro.
If you can beat Russ
in dance-off,
you get a free
plate of wings.
Wear your Snuggie,
get it working!
You got a
Snuggie?
I said you take off
your Snuggie.
No, I don't have one.
Not anymore.
Oh, you did.
♪♪
So, I'm here in
Lahaina, Maui,
with my buddy Reno
from Fresh Catch.
Now, Reno, you come
to Lahaina often?
Yeah, we come up once a year
for a big fishing tournament.
Dig it, dig it. Now, where do
you eat when you come here?
That's a good question.
I talked to some locals,
and they said go down the steps
to Down the Hatch --
that's the place.
♪♪
Lobster and crab
grilled cheese sandwich up!
It's just great to be
in this great island vibe.
-Macadamia nut Mahi Mahi.
-It's family-friendly.
You're outside,
get the fresh air.
-Po'boy bread, done.
-Po'boy right here.
It's where Southern
hospitality meets Aloha.
FIERI: 'Cause
Atlantic transplants
Javi Barberi, David Fincher,
and Julian Bonfardin
are mashing up down-home cooking
with a slice of paradise.
What does a dude from Georgia
know about cooking island food?
It take soul at the same time
that cooking
Southern food takes soul.
It really is the truth.
And you know it doesn't hurt
when you mix in fish
caught right across the street.
-Ahi samurai.
-Ahi samurai is an awesome dish.
It's absolutely delicious.
What are we making?
Our avocado hummus that
goes on the ahi samurai.
First we just have tahini,
garbanzo beans or chickpeas,
100% olive oil, lemon juice.
The only thing left is
just fresh island avocados.
So, this is hummus with
pieces of avocado
versus and avocado mousse
you got here.
Exactly.
Here is half an ahi loin that
we got in earlier today.
Gorgeous.
Let's take off the belly portion
just so we can get
that saku block out.
S-a-k-u?
S-a-k-u -- saku block.
Just the prime-time
loin of it.
Exactly.
Got it.
Next step, kosher salt
and coarse, ground black pepper.
And all we're really
looking for is
just to coat
both sides of it.
Okay.
And then the last
finishing touch
is just taking
a little bit of the furikake,
which is nori
and Japanese spices.
A hot flat top
with a little bit of oil.
And just hot and fast.
Really quick.
Just crusting both sides.
I still want it completely raw
for the majority of it.
Okay.
Now, we're going to take
the toasted baguette,
that avocado hummus
that we made earlier.
Down goes the ahi,
on-island red pickled onions,
wasabi aioli,
clover sprouts.
And then the last is
just a balsamic reduction.
And there's the ahi samurai.
I don't know if I should eat it
or take a picture of it, huh?
♪♪
When you get ahi like that,
you sear it perfectly,
you can't beat it.
Mmm.
Contrast of the pickled onions,
loved the little hummus.
You really do want to take
that and smash it together
and make it a sandwich,
let me tell you.
Now, we are calling
this an appetizer?
We're calling this a...
Calling this an appetizer.
Another thing we kind of
brought from the South
is we like people
leaving full and happy,
so we still someone
a substantial amount, for sure.
Substantial it is, my friend.
Thank you very much.
Nicely done.
-Ahi samurai.
-You get the wasabi in there
with the aioli, the balsamic
gives it a little bit of tang.
Really fresh, local food.
FIERI: There's also known
for their local drinks.
So, as I'm doing all the hard
work in the back,
Reno's been here sampling
all of the beverages.
So, when you
come to Hawaii,
you've got to try
some traditional drinks.
How's the Mai Tai?
Is it legit?
This is the real deal
right here.
How's the pina colada?
This colada good, brudda.
This coldada is good?
And you can pair it up
with the guys' top-selling dish.
MAN: Lobster and crab
grilled cheese.
Lobster, crab, cheese,
amazing Hawaiian sweetbread --
what more can you want?
Okay. That sounds like
really swimsuit weather.
Oh, yeah.
So, I start by just making
the lemon Beurre Blanc sauce.
Oil in the pan, garlic,
shallots, Chablis cooking wine.
Chablis?
Chablis.
Oh, only the fine wine!
Put a little lemon juice
in there, heavy whipping cream.
Butter -- one little block
at a time
to make sure the sauce stays
together and doesn't break.
Doesn't break?
Pinch of salt.
All right, next step?
We build the sandwich itself.
First, a little crab claw meat
and Maine lobster claw meat.
All the way from Maine.
All the way to the island.
Don't you guys have
lobster on the island?
We have spiny lobster
on the island.
The quality difference
is night and day.
I'm timing you to see
if you can get this done
before I eat
all the fries.
I don't know
what's going on here.
A little Cajun blend spice.
Those are dangerous.
Now we're just going to warm
this up on the sauté pan.
It comes cooked.
Just to warm it.
Yes, sir.
So now that
that's good and hot,
we can slice
the Hawaiian sweetbread
to about an inch thickness.
A little bit
of the whipped mayo.
Make sure we get a good,
nice toast going.
Put down the slices
of American, Monterey jack
and cheddar blend.
The lobster and crab,
I just pile it on.
That doesn't look like one
person's eating that anyways.
Got our cabbage.
That's odd. Okay.
Just gives it
a little bit of crunch.
Diced tomatoes, and then we have
that Beurre Blanc sauce.
Once it's grilled both sides,
it's time for plating.
It's a monster, bro.
We just add a little bit
of lava sauce.
What's the lava sauce?
Mayonnaise, Sambal chili paste,
sweet Thai chili sauce,
fresh lemon juice,
and white vinegar.
Take the sandwich,
cut it in quarters.
I'll check the fries.
That's a nice plating.
Thank you.
Then we finish it with a little
bit more of that lava sauce
just 'cause it complements
everything on there.
Your order of fries.
You give more than that, I hope,
'cause it looks like
somebody's already been
eating those.
Certainly.
And a little touch of paprika.
♪♪
Flavor's great.
Nice, big pieces
of lobster in there.
This lava sauce --
really nice.
The Texas toast
is toasted off perfectly.
There's a lot going on.
It's a big,
hearty grilled cheese.
And the fries, I don't know.
You cheated me on that one.
You guys'll dig this.
You're giving it to them.
Nicely done, buddy.
I appreciate that.
Nicely done.
MAN: Lobster and crab
grilled cheese.
-Awesome dish.
-Loaded with lobster.
Grilled perfectly.
MAN #2: This is
one of the places
where you really want
to go and try it.
You made the right stop.
Definitely.
Okay.
FIERI: And when we come back,
we'll check out
the Hawaiian specialty
that got these
three dudes started.
Shave ice.
Tastes like
you're in Hawaii?
Yes.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're at Down the Hatch
in Maui in Lahaina
where three guys from Georgia
got a good thing going
when they opened their spot
the locals and tourists dig.
Such a great place to come.
Really relaxed vibe.
FIERI: But before it was
a full-blown restaurant,
they started small serving up
this tropical specialty.
-A shave ice for you.
-It's a delicious,
refreshing drink
for a hot summer day.
MAN: This reminds me of
when I was little,
shave ice trucks going around.
It's shave ice,
not shaved.
Exactly.
The key is
super cold ice...
Yep.
...shaved super-thin.
That's another huge one.
All right.
So, break it down.
So, we're going
to make mango shave ice.
Okay.
They grow on
the trees everywhere.
It's almost a nuisance in some
places how often they grow.
Yeah, it's really got
to be tough.
Oops, another one
just fell.
How do you deal with it?
So, we just start by
taking the fresh mango.
Cut off the cheeks.
You don't go any farther
into the pit than that?
No. You can go
a little bit further,
but then you start getting
into the bitterness of it.
That's, like,
a real television answer.
I appreciate it.
I'm learning quick.
Now it's sugarcane
simple syrup.
That much?
That much.
When you're talking
about syrup,
you're really
talking about sugar
with a little bit of ingredients
for flavor added in.
Then we just hit it on.
And that's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
There's your
fresh mango, sir.
Dig it.
Now, let's get to the shave.
Grab one of our ice blocks.
Okay.
Grab it in, and then...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what do you got down there?
A little foot pedal.
It's like you're working
at the carnival,
like you run the Zipper
or something.
Hit it!
And you can adjust
the fineness.
You're working the throttle
right there and doing the trim.
Multi-tasking.
And you get a nice little base,
and you just build it up.
I'm so doing this.
There you go.
And now you have to let
this set for a day.
So, this is the strained
and refined?
Yep.
Okay.
And then all you do is
you just paint it on
as thick as you like it.
Seriously?
Oh, yeah.
And then you just finish.
♪♪
Well, the thing I like
about is as soon as you put
a spoonful of it in there,
it just melts.
Yep.
It's like eating a snowball.
Now, here's the only thing.
We've got to be
honest about this.
There's no way to look cool
and carry that.
I'm going to need this in, like
a big, Styrofoam trucker mug.
There you go.
[ Both laugh ]
-A shave ice for you.
-It's, like, tart and sweet.
It's really nice.
It's cold and refreshing.
-Delicious?
-It is.
Lobster grills coming
on the finishing board.
WOMAN: I love Down the Hatch.
The food is fresh,
and the people are cool.
FIERI:
You can have a little sun.
You can have a little shade.
You can have some great food.
You got you characters
to talk to.
Nicely done, buddy.
Thank you very much.
Coming up, a locals' favorite
in Cathedral City, California...
You're giving them
all kinds of flavor.
...where they're
serving up smoke...
That's a competition
brisket right there.
...and fire.
Yeah, that's not going
to be hot or anything.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Cathedral City
which is neighboring town
to Palm Springs, California.
And I'm on Perez Road
in an industrial park.
Hang on. I know
it doesn't sound exciting.
What is exciting is
that a local guy said,
"Hey, all these folks
in the industrial park
need a place to eat."
So he tuned into "Triple D,"
studied up hard,
and opened up his own joint,
named it after his kids.
This is Zobo & Meester's.
GROENDYCKE: Pastrami about
two minutes out.
Zobo & Meester's is kind of like
the cafeteria for the area.
All right.
Let's do the flamethrower.
He's serving breakfast and lunch
to all these people
who are here
during the business day.
Here we have the bacon
cheeseburger mac n' cheese.
The name comes from Zoe and Mia,
his twin daughters.
FIERI: Who were babies
when Bart Groendycke came up
with their nicknames
and the idea to open up shop.
And you're not from
the restaurant business.
No, not at all.
I found a lot of inspiration
from just watching "Triple D,"
and I thought, you know...
Seriously, stop.
[ Laughs ]
It's okay, just stop.
I've got to say, it's good
to see he actually
learned a thing or two.
Scratch-made.
We don't have a freezer here,
so everything's fresh.
Really?
Here's your flamethrower
and French fries.
MAN: The flamethrower is meaty.
It's hot.
One of the Bart's
great sandwiches.
So, what are we
going to make?
Habanero salsa for our
flamethrower panini.
We're going to make a panini
that has habanero salsa in it?
Yes.
I think you'll like it.
Okay.
Got some habaneros here.
Put in a little bit of carrot,
white onion, pineapple juice.
Blend it up a little bit.
Lemon juice, cumin,
salt, fresh garlic.
That's not going to be hot.
Leave some texture to it.
Let it simmer for
about 10 minutes,
and that's the beginning
of this flamethrower.
Yes.
I just want to know
why you call it that.
Now our sirloin tip
and pork shoulder.
Just a salt and pepper rub.
This roast,
we do in the oven,
about 325,
three and a half, four hours.
And we're going to
medium rare on that?
Medium rare, yeah.
And on the shoulder,
what's happening there?
We put it in the smoker
about 190 to 200.
And when it gets to the nice
sweet spot for pulling,
I'll let it rest a little bit
and then pull it apart.
Yep, that'll do.
Take our roast beef,
a little bit of pork here.
Got to get some
of that bark in there.
Pepper jack,
and we give it a steam.
We are going to get ready
for the panini press.
Take our zam sauce.
Zam sauce?
Short for Zoe and Mia.
Okay.
Pulled pork and the top round.
Pickled jalapeños.
Fresh jalapeños.
Yeah, that's not going
to be hot or anything.
Hey, why don't we hit it with
a little bit of habanero salsa?
How long is that going
to go on there, boss?
A minute,
minute and a half.
Okay.
There you go.
It's a good-looking
sandwich.
I'm eating with this
with the anticipation
of a nuclear firestorm
to start in my mouth any second.
Oh, yeah.
Now we're warming up.
Here we go.
Delicious sandwich.
Thank you.
Meat's really
nice and tender.
The habanero salsa
gives a little sting.
The pickled jalapeños
add that nice acidity.
You need some acid to it.
But there's some definitely
some heat coming through that.
[ Laughs ]
-Excellent, brother.
-Flamethrower, fries up.
One of my favorites.
-It packs a heat.
-Yes, it does!
-And I love it.
-All right.
Chicken and brisket ready.
Bart smokes all
of his meats on-site.
I come every Saturday
for the barbecue.
So, you only do barbecue
on Saturday?
Yes.
Yeah, I'm not playing that game,
waiting till barbecue day.
I'm just going
to tell you right now.
Just shut the cameras
off for a second.
Um, you're going to have to fire
the smoker up immediately.
Okay.
Okay?
Just letting you know.
I told you!
Three-meat barbecue sandwich up!
The three-meat sandwich
is one-stop shopping
for Bart's barbecue.
We're going to make
our barbecue sauce.
Ketchup, brown sugar.
A little bit.
Apple cider vinegar,
some yellow mustard, molasses,
and maple syrup.
Black pepper, soy sauce.
There you go.
Smoke flavor, cumin,
onion powder,
garlic,
Worcestershire sauce.
Warshershister,
washyoursister sauce?
Some sage.
Paprika, chili powder,
and a little cayenne.
You've got it.
Let that chicken marinate
in this barbecue sauce
for how long?
Over night.
Into the smoker.
Yes.
Got it.
Next thing we're going to do
is a beautiful-looking brisket
with nice bark.
I don't suppose
you want to try it.
Well,
in the name of science.
Mm. That's a competition
brisket right there.
Tender, pulls apart.
You want to try
a bite of that, huh?
[ Whistles ]
Yep.
The hand says he likes it.
Get a little bit
of the pork.
Then we're going to
pull some chicken.
So, it's mixed together.
Now we're ready to make the slaw
that's going on top
of the the three-meat --
what did you call it?
Three-meat
barbecue sandwich.
How did you come up
with that name?
Start with some mayonnaise.
Apple cider vinegar,
pineapple juice.
That's an interesting one.
Heavy cream, salt, pepper,
celery seed, and sugar.
That is very thin.
It's very light.
Yes.
Slimming.
It is.
Then we take
our three meats.
Add the barbecue sauce.
We got our toasted bun.
Take some coleslaw
that we just made.
No Styrofoam for me.
No Styrofoam?
I'll be good.
Didn't know.
A little bit of our chipotle
sauce, fresh jalapeño.
There you go.
You're giving them
all kinds of flavor.
The slaw's really tasty
with the pineapple juice.
Great barbecue sauce.
Run-down-your-arm
type barbecue.
The bun's dynamite.
You can feed a family
of three with it.
For a guy who didn't do
the restaurant business,
didn't smoke meats before,
you did really good job.
Look at that, huh?
I appreciate it.
Three-meat barbecue
sandwiches, French fries.
-Thank you.
Three-meat.
It's yummy.
And it's a little messy,
[laughs] but delicious.
MAN: You can taste that it
just came out of a smoker,
like you did it
in your backyard.
Here's your Zobo burger
and fries, my favorite.
Everything that they make,
I want.
So I come back.
If you were going to name
this after your girls,
you better make
great food.
And you did it.
Nice job.
Appreciate it, Guy.
Was that a road trip, or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
All right.
We're going to pull the pork
for our
flame-thrower sandwich.
Meow're telling
me that we're...
[ Chuckles ]
Meow?
[ Laughter ]