Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest Diners,
Drive-ins and Dives.
On this trip...
Ay-yi-yi.
Ay-yi-yi-yi.
...it's all about
wonder women...
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
...cooking like
culinary superheroes.
You want another one?
Yes, please.
Like in Orlando...
That is legit.
...where pies are getting
baked up sweet...
Wow.
...and savory.
Chicken pot pie is kind of like
kryptonite for me.
...and meatballs
go from traditional...
It's really good.
...to something you'd
never see coming.
I'm excited to see
how this works.
And pay attention
in Houston...
She gonna learn you
right now.
[ Laughs ]
...'cause Mama's
making Mexican...
I'll have all of that.
...and she means business.
This is not just for TV.
She's the real deal.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Houston, Texas,
right across the street
from where the Astros play,
to check out a joint that was
here before anything was here,
and they're serving up
some real deal Mexican food.
Nice car.
Wait a second.
Was that Jeff Bagwell?
Anyhow, This is Irma's.
Hey wait a second, Baggs!
♪♪
Got your chicken mole.
Above and beyond
a Mexican restaurant.
La Mexicana.
MAN: I've never been
in a restaurant
that knows
their customers' tastes
more unerringly
than these people.
I just always feel like
it's made especially for me.
FIERI:
That's the kind of TLC
Irma Galvan has been putting
into her menu
since the late '80s
when she opened this place.
We call it [speaks Spanish].
We cook just like home.
WOMAN: You feel like you're
a part of the family
and not like
you're in a restaurant.
What kind of Mexican
food is this?
Authentic, home-cooked,
a little Tex-Mex, Mexican food.
Tamales right here!
The tamales are one of the best
I've had here in Houston.
They're not your normal tamales.
MAN: They're really full
of either chicken or pork.
It's just excellent.
We're going to try
to make [speaks Spanish] --
pork roast tamales.
We're going to try
to make some?
Try to make some tamales.
Yeah, it's going
to be really dicey.
We don't know if we're going to
be able to pull it off.
But stick with us.
Okay.
Masa.
Broth.
Pork broth.
All right, so,
we mix that together.
You want some help?
Yes.
So, we're going in
with the manteca.
There you go.
I like when the ratio of masa
to manteca is 50/50.
A little salt.
Yes.
Is this guajillo?
Guajillo.
That's my favorite
of all the chilies.
Guajillo
Or the "gwa-jillio."
[ Chuckles ]
Want to put a little color
in the mesa.
How many tamales do you think
you make in a week?
400.
Do you actually have to
make the production
based upon the schedule
across the street?
The Astros are playing and
stuff like that, we get ready.
Now we do the filling
to go in the tamales.
Yes, we've got
some diced [speaks Spanish].
Pork roast.
So, start with the oil.
Let me tell you
about our pot right here.
Yes, that came over
with Columbus.
[ Laughs ]
And then we add
fresh pork.
It's brought me good luck,
this pot has.
I bet you bring it
with you
to the bingo parlor
and everything.
Now we're gonna add
the garlic.
Salt.
Salt, black pepper.
Cumin.
Chili ancho.
And then we add a little kick
of cayenne peppers in here.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Cayenne pepper sauce.
Yes.
What is over there?
[ Laughs ]
Taste! Taste! Taste!
Oh, I'll have all of that.
So, we're going
to let it reduce down,
then we'll take that
and let it cool,
and then we'll start
to make the tamale.
Take one of these
corn husks.
So, we soak the husk.
Yes. Spread it
with the mesa.
Fill it in
with the carnita, pork.
And we usually put
a little more than enough.
That's what
the recipe says?
Yes.
Now it looks
really thin now.
You've got to remember,
though,
that that mesa
hasn't cooked yet.
So, when it absorbs
that steam,
it's going to puff up
a little bit more.
Have you ever seen
anybody eat one raw?
No.
Me either.
That's dumb.
Who would have thought
of that idea?
I'm going to
check that again.
I'm just going to make sure
everything is okay.
That's great by itself.
You give a big filling.
I mean, this is not just
a little line of meat in there.
And we do it
all the time.
You know, it looks like
you've done this before.
You want another one?
Yes, please.
Okay.
16 more, please.
Ay-yi-yi.
Ay-yi-yi-yi.
We're going to
steam these?
Probably about
an hour and a half.
Can you hear that?
You know what that means?
Eh?
Tamale time.
You want a tamale?
A tamale?
Now where did you
get this recipe from?
My mother.
It's so good.
It's tender, nice,
light, fluffy.
Super flavorful.
Got a little bit of spice.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Fantastic.
This is a tamale
that you went to
somebody's house to have...
like su casa.
WOMAN: Homemade tamales.
This is probably one of the best
tamales I think I've ever had.
Seriously?
Yep.
Nice spice to it, nice
little kick to it, very tasty.
What do you like
about them?
The texture.
Did you just drop texture on me
in fourth grade?
So, my buddy Jeff Baggs here,
and the family.
You used to work right
across the street. Not too bad.
What makes the food
here so great?
How it's made, how it's
prepared, and just the taste.
It's more authentic than any
other Mexican restaurant here.
I think this is the best
Mexican restaurant in the city.
Hands down.
It's just like going home
and seeing your mother.
This is for real, folks,
just so you know.
This is not just for TV.
She's the real deal.
FIERI: And we'll find out
just how much real deal
she's putting into
another Mexican dish...
Chili relleno.
...when we come back.
You kill it.
I mean, it inspires
some dancing.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
Welcome back. We're hanging out
in Houston, Texas,
right over by the stadium
where the Astros play.
We're at Irma's,
and Irma rocks it out.
You will feel like you
are sitting
at your friend's
little casita
having fantastic,
homemade Mexican food.
The food is outstanding.
Here you go --
homemade tamales.
Everything has a lot
of flavor to it.
GALVAN: Chili relleno.
Today, I had
the chili rellenos,
and it was
absolutely phenomenal.
And now what are
we going to make?
We're going to make the filling
for the chili rellenos --
the picadillo.
So, in the chili rellenos,
we're putting picadillo?
Yes. That's
the old-fashioned way.
She gonna learn you
right now.
We're going to start
with your oil.
Okay.
Some ground beef.
So, we brown the meat.
Okay.
Onions.
Cebolla.
Peppers. Tomatoes.
There you go.
Ajo.
Garlic.
Seasoning salt.
Black pepper.
Cumin.
Comino.
So, that cooks and cools
and then it goes inside?
Yes.
I love it.
Tell me the next step.
We take the poblano peppers,
and we roast them
right here over the grill
where the skin will soften up,
and then
we have to peel them.
There's the chili.
We're gonna stuff it
with the picadillo.
Little heaven pockets.
A little touch of flour.
I want to make sure
I get it in there,
into the egg white.
Nice and light. Wow.
Make sure the oil
is hot enough.
'Cause we're gonna
put it down on the seam
when we fry it, right?
Yes.
See how she
just put a little bit of oil
on top to set that?
Ohh, that is fluffy.
Okay, beautiful.
Fresh salsa.
A little tomato,
a little onion.
A little onion,
a little cilantro.
Queso fresco.
One of my favorites.
This is good.
This is a chili rellenos.
Too pretty to eat.
Like a Christmas ornament.
[ Laughs ] I know.
Mmm! It's not
a heavy-weighted batter.
Nice and light.
It's so good.
And there's a little bit of heat
in there from that poblano.
Mmm! You get that really
nice pepper flavor.
A little saltiness
of the queso fresco,
the freshness
of the cilantro.
But the meat?
That is the real deal.
chili rellenos.
Delicious.
I mean, like,
outstanding delicious.
Excellent, well-done,
always fresh.
The meat was good and flavorful.
A little blast
from the past --
Famous Greek joint,
Niko Niko's
where they make the
honey balls -- Remember that?
The machine that would drop them
right into the fryer.
How are things now,
my brother?
Amazing. Amazing.
And this is actually
your recommendation.
Why Irma's?
I remember my mother
doing this --
going to the Farmer's Market,
picking out the groceries,
and she still
does that today.
You tasted the food.
Absolutely.
Carnitas.
Right here.
I love this place.
We always come back.
Nice job, girl. Nice job.
Fantastic.
I understand
why everybody loves you.
You really do make
this your house.
Es mi casa. Yes.
It is.
FIERI:
Coming up, in Orlando...
I'm rolling this
for sure.
...a righteous
restaurant bakery...
There you go now.
...putting their decadent spin
on a childhood classic.
Let's fill your pie hole
with bacon and butter.
♪♪
I'm here in Orlando, Florida,
in the Milk District,
an area known as that
because right down the road
is the T.G. Lee milk factory.
And what kind of restaurant do
you want next to a milk factory?
I know. A bakery.
Not just any bakery --
one that's focusing
on butter and bacon.
And did I mention butter?
Oh, yeah, they've got
to have a tag line like
"Let us fill your pie hole."
This is Se7en Bites.
♪♪
Got a Seventh Heaven.
WOMAN:
It'll blow you away.
Everything's just
so incredibly well-made.
Sausage morning biscuit
for you.
It's like my happy place.
FIERI: In a town known
for its happy places.
But Trina Gregory-Propst
has tapped into the locals
with her own magic
culinary kingdom...
You have a restaurant
as well as bakery.
Yes.
It's all scratch-made.
It is.
...from the sweet
to the savory.
Chicken pot pie.
The chicken pot pie
is awesome.
It's so hard
to get a crust right,
and Trina's got it down.
Chicken pot pie is kind of like
kryptonite for me.
You know, and it's got to be
a little bit
of the Lucille headband
that's rolling it for me.
You know, something
doesn't feel right.
When you're
in my kitchen,
I kind of need you
to have your bandanna on.
I'm rolling this
for sure.
[ Laughter ]
Let's go.
Now we're going to make
our pie crust for the pot pie.
Flour going in.
Salt. Sugar.
We're going to take
this butter in here.
Wow, we're going to take it
right to the rim?
There is no such thing
as too much butter.
So, the key is to make sure
that we're cold enough
with the butter so we can
really make the gravel.
Otherwise,
it just starts to melt,
and you won't get
all the layers. Correct?
That's right.
Then you add ice-cold water.
It's going to just start
to come together.
That's incorporated
enough of the flour.
It is.
You want it to be
as nice and flat as possible.
We're going to let it rest
for 24 hours.
Oh, really?
All right, so,
the chicken.
This is our seasoning
for our chicken breasts.
First you put in thyme,
some pepper,
all four peppercorns
in there.
There you go now.
Next the salt,
and then just sprinkle
that on your chicken.
Be generous.
It's going to cook for 15
to 20 minutes on 350.
Next, we're going to make the
filling for our chicken pot pie.
Dig it.
So, butter makes
everything better.
Our mirepoix.
Sweat those down, a little
salt and pepper into that.
Yeah, and now the thyme.
So, let this cook
for 5 to 10 minutes.
We're just going
to put those in there.
There you go.
We're going to make
our Béchamel in the same pot.
More butter.
Flour.
So, building
a little bit of roux.
A little bit of garlic.
Again, that
four-peppercorn blend.
A little bit of salt.
White wine, milk,
and heavy cream.
We're going to let this cook
for 10 to 15 minutes,
and then it's ready
for our vegetables.
So, potatoes, boiled off.
The peas, frozen.
The chicken breast
we cook down.
Mix it together.
We'll let the pot pie filling
rest overnight,
and it will be ready
to go in the morning.
This is our pie dough
that's rested for 24 hours.
These are our two sizes
that we use for our pot pie.
So, we press that in.
Okay.
It gets a nice,
generous scoop.
Press that down.
Start folding in your dough.
It gets an egg wash
and a sprinkling of celery seed.
About 45 minutes
in the oven, 375.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
It's delicious.
The crust is spot on.
Flaky is not even the word.
Very savory.
The little celery kick
right there.
Oh, yeah.
Most important thing
in a good pot pie is the peas.
It's a great pie,
a great crust.
I have friends
that are this flaky.
[ Laughs ]
Good morning, ladies.
Chicken pot pie.
Flaky crust on
the chicken pot pie is amazing.
You can taste all of the
fresh cream and butter in it.
I could probably finish it,
but I want
to save room for dessert.
The desserts at Se7en Bites
are amazing.
It's like sensory overload.
WOMAN: She's taking some of
the desserts that are nostalgic
from our childhood
and recreated
like a Swiss roll
and an oatmeal cream pie.
GREGORY-PROPST: The vanilla-bean
bourbon bacon moon pie.
Bacon on a moon pie --
Who would ever think of that?
All right,
what are we making?
Moon pie dough.
Oh, I love "moonpiedough."
Yes.
My jocularities
are not amusing her.
First our butter,
confectioner's sugar, cinnamon.
Going to add milk.
Then we're going
to put some honey in.
A.P. flour
and whole-wheat flour.
A little bit of baking powder,
little bit of salt.
That's all she wrote.
That's it.
Roll it out.
Yep.
Bake them at what temp?
300.
For?
14 minutes.
Now we're making
the hot sugar
for our vanilla-bean bourbon
marshmallows.
Some sugar, some water,
glucose.
The most important thing
when you're cooking sugar
is to make sure
you don't have any sugar
on the outside of the pan.
'Cause once you start
that crystallization change --
It's over. You've got
to start all over again.
All right, so,
we're at...284.
This is gelatin. That's gonna
keep it all together.
We're gonna
turn this on.
Got to bring your egg whites
to a stiff peak.
That's not hot or anything.
That hot sugar cooks
the egg white.
That's what makes
the marshmallow.
You know who
the smart one is.
We're going to add
the vanilla beans, the vanilla.
The most important thing --
the bourbon.
I notice we're not
measuring on that.
Yeah, that looks good.
My kind of marshmallow.
And then we let it whip
for 10 minutes.
We're going to pour it
in our sheet pan,
and then it will rest
overnight.
Now that our marshmallow's
firmed up,
sprinkle that bacon
all over it.
Our graham crackers
look and smell awesome.
Cut out our marshmallow.
Put that on top.
That gets a nice, generous
dipping of chocolate.
That is legit.
Ryder, this is all
for you, buddy.
Wow. I've had the homemade
marshmallows before,
but I've never had them
that light.
Those are super silky.
A little bourbon kiss,
and the bacon is spot on.
But the key
to the whole thing,
that is some gangster
graham cracker.
Thank you.
Really nice job.
Moon pie.
There you go. Enjoy.
MAN: This is a guilty pleasure,
definitely.
Absolutely the best.
This place is definitely
worth seeking out.
You will leave happy,
and you will leave very full.
What's
the theme song here?
Come let us fill
your pie hole.
Let us fill your pie hole
with bacon and butter.
Get Se7en Bites.
FIERI: Up next,
one more stop in Orlando...
Ease in.
Be gentle.
[ Chuckles ]
...to a place totally devoted
to the meatball...
Italian 101, baby doll.
...even the ones
without meat.
This is something
to write home about.
Thank you.
[ British accent ]
A little action!
A little action, please!
Yes, righty-oh!
♪♪
So, I'm here in Orlando,
Florida, right off of the 408.
Right between the Space Coast
and the theme parks.
And along for this ride is
"Next Food Network Star" winner
and my buddy, Justin Warner.
Now Justin,
when you come to Florida,
what kind of food
are you thinking?
God, it could be
about mofongo,
it could be
a Cuban sandwich,
it could be seviche,
it could be.
Just slow it down, buddy.
This is real easy.
This is
The Meatball Stoppe.
ISABELLA: Chicken Marsala
over penne pasta!
This place is
a meatball lover's heaven.
Jeffy, I need
a meatball smash.
I'm a transplanted
New Yorker.
To me,
this is Little Italy.
FIERI: Not surprising,
since Chef and Owner
Isabella Morgia di Vicari
is a first-generation American
from Italy.
And she and her husband Jeff
are serving up
her grandma's recipes
while carrying on
another family tradition.
My family owned and operated
six Italian restaurants
in Orlando since 1972.
Why a Meatball Stoppe?
Who doesn't love meatballs?
WOMAN: This is the sausage,
pepper, and onion.
FIERI: And even though they
serve up plenty of variety...
The Buffalo
chicken meatball smash.
...they're not bailing
on the basics.
What are we making first?
Nona's traditional
meatballs.
I'm ready.
All right.
We're going to start
our tomato sauce.
Extra virgin olive oil,
fresh garlic, anchovies,
a little bit
of the crushed red
and then
the whole plum tomato.
Now, oregano, kosher salt,
and then I'm going
to put my gloves on,
because --
the old-fashioned way.
Nature's whisk.
That's exactly it.
Nature's whisk?
That's what you call it?
Yeah.
I'm just going to crush them
just a little bit.
Now, how long is this going
to go in the oven, at what temp?
400 for an hour.
We want a beautiful char
on the top.
That's where
all the favor is.
Now you're going to hit it
with the immersion blender.
Does Nona know that
you're using all these recipes
and giving them away
on TV right now?
All day long, sweetheart.
Okay, here we go.
We're making
our traditional meatballs.
Fresh garlic.
We're going to add
the basil, parsley.
I'm going to add
a little bit of water in here.
All right.
Ground chuck.
Ground pork,
garlic, and fresh herbs.
Now I have eggs, milk,
bread crumbs,
Romano cheese, cayenne.
I like a kick.
Kosher salt. Here we go.
Do you love meatballs?
Honestly, I don't.
Italian is not
in my wheelhouse.
I never had a Nona,
you know?
[ Giggles ]
Then I'm going to form
the balls with my scoop.
I'm going to bake them
in the oven
for 12 minutes
at 400 degrees.
And you do leave them flat
on one side?
I do.
I can tell you an advantage
though of the flat bottom
is that you eliminate,
"I lost my poor meatball.
It rolled away."
you know what I mean?
Before we serve the meatballs,
we simmer them
in roasted tomato sauce and
chicken stock for 45 minutes.
Okay, what's
this concoction?
This is
creamy polenta.
Got it.
And the secret is I hit it
with the immersion blender.
Super creamy.
Now I add these
beautiful meatballs,
hit it with a little bit
of Italian parsley,
fresh basil,
and we're good to go.
Mmm.
It's really good.
It's a cross between
light and dense.
A lot of meatballs,
in my opinion, are too dense.
This, when
you bite into it,
there's a good amount
of moisture.
I've never had
polenta immersion-blended.
Have you?
No, no, no.
It's a good thing.
Is it?
Yeah, it's smart.
Do you like
the flavor?
Yeah.
Delicious.
Really nice.
It's very juicy on the inside.
It falls apart in your mouth.
The tomato sauce is tart, and
it's got a little sweetness.
WOMAN:
I come from an Italian family,
and it's like
being back at home.
FIERI: Where three generations
work together,
since their daughter and
Isabella's mom also help out.
Everything about the restaurant
is revolved around family
and the tradition of having
a great meal together.
ISABELLA: Vegetarian meatball
on the white bean ragu.
I never thought you could do
a vegetarian meatball.
Right.
It's so good.
Once you pair it off with
some pesto sauce, you're done.
Okay, so, now
we're onto vegetarian meatballs.
Yes.
Give us the rundown.
We've got carota,
carrots.
Mushrooms.
Oh, you don't like
the mushroom in Italian?
Funghi.
Absolutely.
All right,
I'm just making sure.
Onions, garlic, celery,
kosher salt and pepper,
and olive oil.
I'm going to roast these 400,
about 30 minutes.
Okay. We're back.
We're roasted. We're cooled.
Now we're going
to the food processor.
I'm excited to see
how this works.
I'm a little skeptical
at times.
Yes, I've had
more bad vegetarian meatballs
than I've had good.
I'm going to puree
half the vegetables with basil
and half with parsley.
Now, beautiful
cooked lentils.
Ahh.
Getting mental
with my lentil.
I see where
you're going with this.
Lentils have a natural
emulsifying property.
Yes, it does.
That's going to be the glue
that makes it go.
So, we've got the mixture
with the lentils.
Going to add the egg, lemon,
oil mixture.
The oregano.
Kosher salt.
Gluten-free bread crumbs.
And of course, Romano.
Now, there they go.
These are going to roast off
in the oven.
400, 12 minutes.
Okay, let's do it.
We're going to plate these
with a white bean ragu.
We're going to top them,
a little fresh Italian parsley.
[ Speaks Italian ]
Bon Appetito.
I'll tell you this --
They're super tender.
I mean, I like a meatball
that's barely holding together.
I think the lentils is
the real kicker to this.
There's a creaminess to it.
Silky. Yep.
Silky.
The mushrooms,
that's coming out really strong.
The pesto is that nice,
bright, fresh, light acidity.
Out of the two meatballs,
I like the vegetarian the most.
Yeah, seriously.
Thank you.
Not only would
you have had me fooled,
but then
when you told me,
my mind would have
just been blown.
This is something
to write home about.
Thank you.
Very nice.
Vegetarian with
a white bean ragu for you.
It's tender. Let me just -- Mmm.
I'm so hungry.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
It's even filling up my buddy,
former baseball player,
A.J. Pierzynski.
If you wouldn't have told me
it was vegetarian,
I never would have guessed.
It's the lentils
in it, right?
I probably have never had
one of those.
You never had a lentil?
Ease in. Be gentle.
Yeah, be gentle
to the lentil.
ISABELLA: Ready to go!
Jeff and Isabella have
extreme passion
not only for their food,
but for the people
that they serve.
Well, thank you
for having us,
and Justin's going to stay here
for the next week
and work for you.
I love it.
Italian 101, baby doll.
There you go.
So, was this
a great road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
Who's got the chili rellenos
and the mole?
Who's got it?
I knew Jeff Bagwell
worked here!
[ Laughs ]