Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Rolls Rs on tongue]
...we're kicking it in Cancun...
I bring you to
the right places or what?
...soaking up
the flavors in Mexico.
That is the nacho crown
in the kingdom of Flavortown.
Like righteous rellenos
and gangster gorditas...
That's worth
a plane ticket by itself.
...cooked up
by one rocking grandma.
She's dangerous.
And an artistic oasis...
This is a big surprise.
...where out of the box
is the name of the game.
The creativity is like
something I haven't seen before.
Then at Playa Del Carmen...
Come on!
...I'm giving you
a one-of-a-kind
behind-the-scenes
look at my new restaurant.
It's my recipe,
I still get wowed.
That's all right here,
right now on,
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
♪♪
[ Mexican music plays ]
Oh, man, I love Cancun, Mexico.
Been here a bunch of times.
Everyone once in a while,
I want to break off
of the tourist areas
and go where the locals are.
So I'm here in the center
in an area known as Nichupte.
Now this is about
a 20-minute cab ride
from the hotel zone
and well worth it.
'Cause I'm here
to check out a joint,
three generations serving up
Mexico City specialties.
This is El Rincon
de los Antojos.
Man:
"El Rincon de los Antojos,"
means the corner of cravings.
Chicken quesadilla.
All the smells,
the tastes are beautiful.
-And Mexican pambazo.
They all have
grandma's recipes.
And they actually have grandma
herself, Carmen Rascon Niedes,
who runs this joint
with her daughter Barbara
and granddaughter Fernanda,
all with roots
in Mexico City.
So this is a Mexico City
style...
Yeah.
...Mexican restaurant
in Cancun.
We call it garnachas.
Garnachas.
What is the translation
for "garnachas"?
-Like, "cravings."
-Cravings, okay.
This is with original recipes
like gorditas or empanadas
from different states
of Mexico.
Chile relleno...
There is a lot of places around
to get chile relleno,
but the best one
is actually here.
FIERI:
What are we making?
So we're going to do the sauce
for the chile relleno.
-The chile relleno.
-Chile relleno.
Everybody should be rolling
their R's at home right now.
And then you're just going to
just start doing like --
-I can't --
-Like naturale.
I do that,
I'll start shaking it all.
-Rrr!
-Let it flow.
-She'll be here all week.
GIARDIELLO:
First, we're going to
blanch some tomatoes.
-Now the onion.
-And the garlic.
Then we're going to
put it in the blender.
That's right. A little bit
of chicken base. Salt.
Chicken base
and salt.
♪♪
-Now in the pan.
-We have some onions.
We're going to strain this
to get the seeds
and the skin
of the tomato off.
-Yeah.
-A little bit of the cinnamon.
Now we're going to
make the chile relleno.
We take the poblanos,
put 'em on the grill.
-Yeah.
-Then take the skin off
and take the seeds out
and leave just a nice,
little pocket.
Very nice.
So now we're going to
stuff it, and this is...?
GIARDIELLO:
Panela cheese.
Show me the magic.
We're going to start
with the egg whites,
and she's going to
do the magic.
The meringue
that this is going to make
is going to create
this nice,
light, fluffy exterior
of the chile relleno.
This is the key.
So when you get stiff peaks,
she can add the yolk.
-Now?
-Corn flour.
So that's it --
a nice, little whipped --
We call it
punto de turrón.
Okay.
That's what I would call it.
So the panela in there,
dredge it in the flour,
and then the batter
will stick to the flour.
We got hot oil,
and we just put it in.
See this little thing
she's doing here?
Splashing it up on top,
so kind of tempering the dough
so she's not just
cooking on one side.
-Then she rolls it over.
-You like it?
-Bonita.
-Bonito.
-Bonito or bonita?
-Damn!
-She is bonita.
I know
she's bonita.
So we're putting
the tomato sauce.
You got to smell this.
Soft plantain on top, huh?
-And the crema.
-Cream.
Look at the colors.
[ Conversing in Spanish ]
♪♪
When you have
a chile relleno
and you have it made
by a grandmother
in a restaurant
three generations
and they do everything
by hand,
everything bought
at the market today,
there's no way
to explain...authenticity
than to just smile.
That chile relleno
right there
is like the moment
right now, right here.
You get a little bit
of the plantain,
get a little bit of the chili,
and the crema.
♪♪
Everything together,
that's the bite.
-Thank you.
-Fantastic.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
Scrumptious.
The exterior is really fluffy,
but then when you bite into it,
it's kind of crunchy.
I've never seen it
with the plantain.
Is that normal?
Yes, for here,
for this region, yes.
We always bring people
from other countries
to taste the food,
because here, we know they'll
have the really Mexican food.
Oh, I'm from Chicago, but
my family, my aunt lives here.
It's pretty nice to have an aunt
that has a place down in Cancun.
-We're here for our wedding.
-They're getting married.
-Oh, you're getting married?
-On Saturday.
Congratulations!
That's awesome.
-Mexican pambazo.
-You want to come to Mexico,
you want to have
the real deal experience.
That's worth
a plane ticket by itself.
FIERI: And if that's not enough
to call your travel agent,
Grandma's got another trick
up her sleeve.
-Le chicharron gordita.
-It's a really tasty food.
I've never seen this ever.
Unbelievable.
FIERI:
Coming up right after the break.
♪♪
So welcome back.
"Triple D"
is here in Cancun, Mexico.
You got
to love Cancun.
And we are at --
help me with the name.
-El Rincon...
-...de los Antojos.
-...de -- like she said.
De los Antojos.
And what it means
is the corner of the cravings.
FIERI: Which is the territory
of the power trio
made up by grandma, daughter,
and granddaughter.
I will tell you this,
I just had a chile relleno
that'll knock your socks off.
You can come here
and enjoy good Mexican food.
It makes your mouth,
like, water.
Two chicharron gordita.
Enjoy.
Le chicharron gordita,
it's like a Mexican
little sandwich,
and chicharron is pork skin.
It's really amazing.
[ Chuckles ]
What are we
going to make now?
-Quajillo sauce.
-Okay, quajillo sauce.
GIARDIELLO:
For chicharron gorditas.
So we're going to put oil.
I see my favorite chili,
the quajillo chili.
-Pancho Villa.
-[ Laughs ]
Bandito.
And we're going to
toast the chilis.
-Exactly.
-The stems are off,
but the seeds
are still in there.
Yeah, 'cause that's
going to give it the --
-Little bit of the heat.
-Yeah.
So the chilis with garlic,
little bit of the oil.
-All of the oil.
-Okay. Good.
GIARDIELLO:
And some water and salt.
Fantastic. Next?
Put it directly
on the chicharron.
-Directly.
-Yeah.
So sometimes
they sell chicharron
with a little bit
of meat on it.
And this is
very well-known in Mexico.
This is cooked.
What do we do from here?
Put it in a molino
and then chop it up.
And we're going to
take that meat
and that flour
and make it together.
And that's what's called
gordita.
Gorditas.
And this is masa harina.
Corn flour, and the other one
is trego flour.
Baking powder, salt.
-Now some water.
-Yep.
Does your grandmother
ride a Harley-Davidson?
-No.
-No?
No.
Does she play lead guitar
in an Iron Maiden cover band?
-No.
-Does she have any tattoos?
No,
but she wants to make one.
-She wants to make a tattoo?
-Yeah.
With my mom
and with me.
That's -- of course she does.
Gangster.
So we're going to put the sauce
on the chicharron.
Oh, this is going
inside the dough?
That's right.
And she's going to
give it a round form.
To put a little of
the chicharron in the middle.
-Yeah.
-There we go.
Oh, no?
Wasn't time
to clap yet.
Okay, so now it's formed
inside of the dough.
-We're going to fry it.
-Of course.
All right.
I've never seen this ever.
-Really?
-Never, ever, ever.
I've never been
to Mexico City.
Now we're going to
cut it open.
-Yeah.
-Like an already-made hamburger.
-We add some onion.
-Cilantro.
-Crema.
-Queso fresco?
-Yeah.
-So you eat it like a hamburger?
♪♪
It's fantastic.
-Tomatillo?
-[ Speaks Spanish ]
Ah. I don't know
how to describe this.
The chicharron
is so good.
It's crunchy and salty,
it's deep flavor,
it's fresh flavor,
it's not too heavy.
And what's this salsa?
GIARDIELLO: Red tomato,
cilantro, onion, garlic.
I thought that I had tried
everything Mexican.
Never have I seen that.
Unbelievable.
I'll take 12 of these
to go, please.
MAN: Cheese, cream,
spicy sauce on the top.
That's the --
the perfect combination.
I don't see this everywhere.
'Cause you have to go
to the little places.
Markets, maybe.
But markets
in Mexico City?
-Yeah.
-[ Speaking Spanish ]
Huh? I bring you to
the right places or what?
It's very nice to come and
have some real Mexican food.
Outrageous.
She's dangerous.
Going to get a tattoo
right there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
[Speaking Spanish]
-Huh?
-Gracias.
♪♪
FIERI:
Coming up, we're hitting an
honest to goodness hidden gem...
Out of bounds.
...where you got to be
in the know to go.
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
This kind of makes me
like Columbus.
Then later, a peek at a place
I never thought would happen.
FIERI: Yes, I do speak about it
as a proud father.
That's my baby
right there.
♪♪
So I told you
I got something
really cool coming up.
Well, but first,
I'm looking for this place.
Now, I'm here
in downtown Cancun,
and no, not the hotel area
that everybody knows of.
And I'm looking for a joint
for the locals.
It has no sign and actually,
you can't get in
unless you have a reservation.
And it's called Mora Mora.
Let's see if this is it.
Password?
The blue zebra
has no spots.
-Come in.
-This is it.
♪♪
[ Man speaking Spanish ]
Once you get in,
it's just magical.
Mora Mora is a little oasis
in the middle of downtown.
FIERI: That's because
after cooking school,
chef and owner
Christian Rodriguez got inspired
while traveling the globe
as a photographer.
Now he's serving up
his Mexican, Asian,
Italian menu in the place
where his journey began.
-This was your home?
-Yeah, yeah.
I grew up here.
-What am I standing in
right now?
What used to be the living room.
Couch here.
Does your family know
what you're doing to the house?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
MAN:
It's a really cool place to be.
Walking through the art gallery,
you start seeing
graffiti everywhere.
-Neither is his cooking.
-Pork belly burger ready.
It has beef and pork belly
with vegetables.
It's awesome.
-Well, what are
we going to make?
-The pork belly burger.
So what we're doing
right now is the broth.
First, we're going to
put the oil.
Next,
I will add pork bones,
put in the carrots,
onions, garlic, zucchini,
and salt and pepper.
-We'll let that cook.
Now we're going to
hit that with water.
-Yeah.
-And that's going to make
the broth that we're going to
cook the pork belly in.
-Yes.
-How long is this going to go?
It takes at least
between three and four hours.
What happens
on a hot day in here?
We sweat a lot.
Yeah?
[ Laughter ]
Now we're going to season
our pork belly in sugar.
-Sugar?
-Yeah.
Salt and pepper.
And then
we're going to tie it up.
We're going to sear
the pork belly.
And all this is going together
just for a burger?
Just for a burger.
And cook it in the broth.
-Now what's our next step?
-Our Asian marinade.
Soy sauce, amaran,
and sugar, a little bit garlic.
-Green onion?
-Green onion.
Okay, so you want
to take this,
hit it with the marinade,
let it go for a little bit.
Are we going to cut this?
-Yeah, we slice it.
-To serve it with the burger.
-Yeah.
Okay, now we're going to
make the burger.
We mix beef and pork,
and then we make our marinade.
-Got it.
-Oil, onions.
-Garlic.
-And parsley.
Salt.
Almost like
a chimichurri?
Kind of, yeah.
Pepper.
Oh, that's got to be
tons of flavor.
So we'll take that,
form it up,
crust it in a skillet.
-Put the cheese.
So now we're going to assemble
our pork belly burger.
-Let's see it, buddy.
-We make here our own mayo.
Then we go
for the patty,
we go for the lettuce,
tomato, cucumber,
some caramelized onions.
Now the pork belly, bacon,
and mustard, ketchup.
Close it up, stab it.
Some oil.
Hope you like it.
Brother, if it's funky,
I'll find it.
This kind of makes me
like Columbus.
Flavor of the burger
is fantastic.
The creativity is like
something I haven't seen before.
Oh, thank you.
There's so much
going into one little burger.
Flavor from the pork belly
to the burger itself,
to the onion, to the bacon,
to the homemade mayo.
-I mean, all of it.
-Thank you.
Dude, you killed it.
That is a legit burger.
Pork belly burger ready.
MAN: The extra little bit
of pork belly on top makes it --
makes it something
that you've never had before.
It's really juicy,
it's really well-made.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
MAN:
Christian's amazing
because he's --
he's trying something different.
He adds little extra touches
to the food.
We change the menu every
eight or every nine months.
Every few months,
you're just going to change it?
-Yeah, yeah.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MAN:
Every time you come, there's
something different on the menu.
It's never, never boring.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Tartar de kamaji is tuna,
tomato, little avocado,
hot pepper on the top.
Now we're going to make
tartar of kamaji.
Let's do it.
We're going to start
with slicing the tuna.
-Ginger.
-Got it.
Bamboo chutes
and red onion,
grape tomatoes,
yerba buena leaf.
Yerba buena, nice.
-Cilantro.
-Little avocado to that.
-Got it.
-Some lime.
Salt, pepper,
some sesame oil, green onion.
And going to make
the plate.
♪♪
This is a special chili pepper
from the region we call shakti.
♪♪
Then sesame seeds.
And it's done.
Crazy.
The little subtleties
like the shakti pepper,
with the grape tomato,
with the sesame oil,
with the yerba buena,
is all over the map.
I'm Asian, then it's Mexican,
and Mediterranean.
But so good.
Out of bounds.
Nicely done, Chef.
The acid of the lime
brings up all the flavor.
What do you think?
How is it?
Amazing.
This place
is as real as it gets.
You're looking
for an adventure,
you want to try
eclectic food,
Mora Mora
is your place.
I really got to be honest.
This is a big surprise.
Chef, great job.
-Thank you.
Don't go anywhere.
I got something really cool
coming up.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
So I've been hinting about it
the entire show.
I got something
really special for you.
Actually, it's really special
for me.
I've been coming to Mexico
since I was a little kid.
Had the opportunity
to open Guy's
in the Cancun Airport,
that was huge.
But to open one here
on Fifth Avenue,
you know I'm out of my mind.
This is Guy Playa Del Carmen.
♪♪
Mac 'n' cheese
bacon burger.
I fell in love
with the flavoring.
Sashimi won ton tacos.
We really like it because
it was, like, really different.
FIERI: Which is the whole idea,
to create a unique menu
using Mexican ingredients
combined with American flavors.
You come to Mexico,
you have great street tacos,
you have great seafood.
But after about day three,
you're kind of like, "hey, man,
where can I score
some buffalo wings?"
-Are we bringing that to people?
-You are bringing it to people.
-You have the trash can nachos.
-The trash can nachos,
I think the way they present it
was amazing.
The moment I saw it, I was like,
"I should order that."
This is our executive chef,
Chef Tanya.
So I know the recipe,
but this is your kitchen,
so you start it off.
Brown sugar, sea salt,
black pepper,
dried mustard,
celery salt.
-This is cumin, your favorite.
-Cumino, yeah.
Chili powder, paprika,
ground garlic, and espresso.
Now, did you think
that was strange
the first time
that you saw that?
-A lot.
-[ Laughs ]
All right,
now a pork butt.
Something I learned
when I first got into barbecue
is just doing a little rub
of wet mustard.
Little bit of that tang.
You want me to sprinkle?
-Mm-hmm.
-We're going to let this set up,
and then we're going to
go to the smoker.
Have you ever smoked meat
before you worked here?
But what do you think?
Okay, so how long
is this going to take?
-Almost 14 hours.
-It's a good-looking pork.
That's what
we're looking for.
All that
really nice smoke
that's gotten all the way
through this.
Nice, crunchy bark
on the outside.
Oh!
What do you think?
The best.
Okay,
so let's get started.
Fresh tortilla chips.
The super melted cheese.
First we start with a roux
of butter, flour, and milk.
Then we add provolone,
cheddar cheese,
gouda, and Swiss.
And then a little bit of salt
and a little bit of Tabasco.
And then the black bean,
cheddar cheese.
And then some of
the pulled pork,
sear it off
on the flattop.
Exactly.
Now, this would be great
just by itself,
but they would
get cold, trust me.
Okay.
We put some SMC
on the base of the plate,
then the trash can,
and we add the nachos.
And we got to make sure
we pack it down a little bit.
Pico de gallo
right in the middle
and the rest
of the chips.
-More pico.
-The sour cream, cotija cheese.
Cotija, my favorite.
Perfect.
The pickled red onions.
Super-thin-sliced jalapeños.
And cilantro leaves.
We smash them
like three times.
All right.
[ Drumroll ]
And then the stack
of the nachos.
Come on!
That is the nacho crown
in the kingdom of Flavortown.
[ Chuckles ]
The cheese, the beans,
you got the cotija,
the pico de gallo,
the jalapeños.
Yes, I do speak about it
as a proud father.
That's my baby
right there.
It's got a little bit
of everything on there,
right there.
You get a lot of flavor.
It's not just one note.
What's your favorite part?
-The cotija cheese.
♪♪
-You killed it.
You're the best.
Come on.
You'll want to eat
everything she makes.
Trash can nachos up.
When you come to down
to vacation in Playa del Carmen,
you got to bring
some of your best friends.
So this
is Paul Thompson.
He's traveled
all over the country,
all over the world
with me.
This, by far,
is my favorite.
And she keeps trying
to steal my plate, too.
I have it over --
-Well, she's your wife.
It's 50/50.
She only gets some of
the things 50/50, not my chips.
[ Laughs ]
I could try it again
and again and again.
Okay, what do you want
to make next, Chef?
Ceviche?
-Ceviche.
So we've got
the lightly poached shrimp.
-Pico de gallo.
-Little cucumber.
You get the avocado
in there.
This is
a tequila marinade.
So this is our little bit
of lemon, tequila, cilantro.
And lime juice,
cumin.
I mean, that's what
we're talking about.
All in small bits,
so when you put it onto a chip,
you're getting
a little bit of everything.
Excellent.
You guys are
executing it perfectly.
There's one more thing
I got to try.
We only offer it
down here
at Guy Playa,
and that's the shrimp tacos.
Will you make me one?
-Of course.
The shrimp taco was amazing.
This is the best taco
I ate in my life.
Do your magic,
sister.
The tortillas cooked off
on the flattop.
Then we add the shrimps.
That we just
lightly fried.
The pink chili mayo.
It's really that pink
peppercorn mayo that makes this.
Then we have the slaw
already dressed
with a little bit
of citrus.
It has
an orange zest.
Little bright,
fresh against the mayo.
Pickled red onions finished
with the cilantro leaves.
Okay,
let's look at this.
♪♪
Here's the key.
When everything's
made so fresh,
when that slaw was just tossed
with a little bit of the citrus,
and it's that orange zest
inside that really makes it.
And you get the vinegar coming
through from the pickled onions.
It's not overdone,
it's not underdone,
it's just
a complete balance.
Fantastic. Delicious.
-Thank you.
-Lava shrimp tacos.
Sauce is great,
the cabbage is fresh.
Straight on point.
Exactly what
it's supposed to be.
The menu is good, always fresh.
This is
my partner in crime.
This is Rafael
of the MERA Corporation.
These guys have held
the standard really high.
You, my sister...
This is the rock star
at Guy Playa del Carmen.
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
[ Conversing in Spanish ]
-Ah!
-[ Laughs ]
I was going to dance
like that.
Hey, a party!
Okay.