Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hey!
...we're digging up
some island treasures...
I like the beginning
of this deal.
...and discovering
a desert oasis...
Oh, this is
that kind of place.
...which is actually in
Palm Desert, California...
Well played,
my friend.
...where breakfast and lunch
is savory and sweet...
You won't like these.
Never come here.
[ Laughs ]
...and in Maui...
Okay.
I'm down with it.
...a place that's gluten-free
and full of flavor...
That's crazy.
...plus, a funky joint
in Virginia Beach...
I like the way this guy works.
He's got his own style.
... where things get
a little out of control
[ Laughs ]
with the Caribbean.
The food's great, but come down
for the floor show.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
Hey, excuse me.
Excuse me.
Can you tell me
where Wilma & Frieda's is?
That way?
Thank you.
FIERI:
Well, I guess the '68 can't
pull right up to this one.
I'm here at The Gardens
on El Paseo
in Palm Desert,
California,
and I'm looking for
this funky joint
where a brother and sister
have teamed up to give you
an eclectic breakfast and lunch
experience you won't forget.
This is Wilma & Frieda.
Blackberry custard
French toast.
We like to think of it
as the rising star
of the Coachella Valley
when it comes to restaurants.
Meatloaf
and eggs over easy.
Comfort food,
but with a delectable twist.
FIERI: The kind of food
that made Kelly McFall
ditch her corporate life
and recruit her brother,
Craig Alexander,
to open a joint named
after their grandmothers.
And now they're dishing
down-home to a high-end crowd.
El Paseo's kind of known as
the Rodeo Drive of the desert.
Oh, this is
that kind of place.
We were kind of
the casual place.
The meatloaf's ready,
Chef.
So, who am I
cooking with?
Chad's our chef.
He is amazing.
Okay.
And we have Camilla
as our pastry chef.
So I get to cook
with both of them?
SPEARS: Short-rib melt
on sourdough.
The short-rib melt
is incredible.
MAN:
You can't get it anywhere else.
It's definitely
an experience in itself.
Well,
what are we making?
SPEARS: We're going to
braise the short rib
for the short-rib melt.
So, we start out with
the boneless short rib,
black peppercorn,
garlic cloves, bay leaves.
A lot of bay leaves.
Brown thyme,
kosher salt,
a whole gallon
of Burgundy red wine.
Burgundy?
Is it 'cause
it's "out-of-the-box"?
[ Laughs ]
Mirepoix.
Now you're going to get
all splashy-splashy, Chef.
All your blue shirts
get splashed.
Are you a fan of me?
Yeah, I'm a fan of all
of your blue shirts.
You've got some issues,
son.
This is a strong beef base,
and we braise it overnight
at 250 degrees.
I like the way
this is going.
All right, boss,
what are we into now?
We are making
pickled red onions.
Red wine vinegar.
Water.
A whole bunch
of coriander.
Black peppercorn,
crushed red pepper flakes,
Bay leaf.
You and your bay leaf!
It's like me
and my blue shirt.
Huh?
Kosher salt.
I let it come to a boil.
Onions go in, steep for
an hour and a half.
Short ribs are
finished braising.
That is pull-apart
short rib all day long.
Right?
Strain the jus.
We're going to
mix the mirepoix.
[ Whirring ]
That is music to my ears.
And I reincorporate
it back into the meat.
Ohh!
Now we start
to make this melt.
I put oil down,
typically sourdough bread.
All right.
Monterey Jack cheese,
6-ounce portion of short rib,
pickled red onions.
Sauté the arugula
right behind it.
Got it.
Cook it all up.
Add it together.
♪♪
Nice move!
That's like Fonzie, dude.
This is a Fonz move.
"Yo, Cunningham!"
Short rib's tender.
Arugula is
a really nice touch.
But the kicker that makes me
want to take another bite
of this sandwich
each time is what?
Pickled red onion?
This guy's got it.
Thank you.
Well played, my friend.
Give me one more Fonzie.
"Hey-y-y-y!"
It's got
a lot of flavor.
You can really taste,
like, the wine in there.
It's so moist, and the meat
is just amazing.
You don't hear
"moist" enough.
You don't.
I'm for more "moist."
[ Laughs ]
The Hand says he is.
Well,
save room for dessert.
WOMAN: The pastry selection
is amazing.
I've grabbed cookies and cake
pops and things for my kids.
I've had several breakfast tarts
here, and they're all delicious.
Tell me if I get
sugar on my face.
It's got really great
fruity filling.
Very nostalgic.
So, today, we're making
the Wilma & Frieda
breakfast tart.
Okay.
Let's get into it.
We're going to start
with the blueberry compote.
I got fresh blueberries,
some lemon juice,
and granulated sugar.
We're going to let
that cook down.
In the meantime,
we're going to make a slurry.
Okay.
So this is cornstarch
and water.
There we go.
It's going to get thick, and
then it's going to cool down,
and we're going to use
that in our breakfast tart.
We're going to make
the dough now?
Yes.
Awesome.
Did you notice
my blue shirt?
Yes, I did.
Thank you.
Great shirt.
All-purpose flour, sugar,
kosher salt, nutmeg,
some vanilla extract,
shortening, and butter.
So we're making gravel.
Yes.
And we have ice water.
So, this is all going
to pull together,
and we're going
to roll it out.
Don't get any of that
on my blue shirt.
Don't you start!
I won't, I won't.
All right.
Down to about a centimeter.
And then we're going to use
a pastry cutter.
Time to party.
And we go the other way.
And this is where
the blueberry compote comes in.
And we take one more piece
and some egg wash,
and we paint it
like Picasso.
Ooh. Okay.
And we use
a pastry crimper here.
We got to make sure
we seal it.
That's going to
glue it shut.
Yes.
What are we
baking these at?
350.
For how long?
10 minutes, and we're
going to pull it out,
put milk on it, and put it back
in for 10 minutes.
And that
creates the glaze?
Yes.
Dig it!
Learning something today.
Pick a card -- any card.
This one.
You're playing lead dog
on this?
You're in my house.
Ooh!
All right, if that's the one
you think I want.
This is our frosting here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Sprinkles!
What happened?
This is a sprinkles.
We finish it with powdered sugar
and some fresh blueberries.
Good seller?
Yes.
♪♪
Oh, you won't like these.
Never come here.
[ Laughs ]
That's ridiculous.
It's like shortbread
meets awesome piecrust
meets a morning
breakfast tart.
Wow! The compote in the middle
is really great.
That's the key to it.
I do like the little
crunchy things, though.
If you're going to eat
something that decadent,
it better be handmade.
It better have a lot
of flavor to it.
Just delicious.
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
WOMAN: It's a perfect amount
of sweetness
with a little bit
of salty crust there.
Like Grandma's homemade pie.
Amazing.
Ah, come on.
Blackberry custard
French toast.
Wilma & Frieda is one
of my favorite breakfast spots.
Tops your day off
in a great way.
I'm always a fan
of seeing
brothers and sisters
work together,
and to see that
you honor family.
Are your grandmas
still with you?
No.
No, they passed away.
Did they know about
the naming?
Wilma did.
That's why it's
Wilma & Frieda's.
Yes.
We had to put her first.
FIERI: Next up, something's
missing at this Maui spot.
Wow!
But by the taste of things,
you'd never know it.
I mean, that's the crunch
you want.
So we're looking
for a cornmeal texture.
Where are you looking at?
I'm looking at you
and into your eyes.
Yes. Deep. Ah.
♪♪
You know, on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
we have found great
Chinese food in Canada.
We've also had Russian food
in Cuba
and American barbecue
in London.
So it's not too surprising to me
that we would come across
a gluten-free restaurant
here in Maui.
This is Maui Brick Oven.
We got 2 minutes
left on the first pizzas.
You'll never believe
that it's gluten-free.
I got the breaded
mozzarella sticks coming at you.
You're not
gluten-intolerant?
No.
We come here
because we love it.
FIERI: Which is exactly
what dad-and-son duo
Terry and Chad Covington
was hoping for --
a joint losing the gluten
but keeping the flavor.
About 6 years ago,
I found out
I had this condition
called celiac disease.
My son, who is a chef
on the big island,
was also
sick with it, too,
so we decided to open
up this restaurant
because he can still cook
and I had something to do.
FIERI: I had a chef on
"Guy's Grocery Games"
that made a gluten-free
pizza dough, and it was
some of the best pizza
we'd ever seen on the show.
I bet you our pizza crust will
be as good as that or better.
Okay.
I'm down with it.
The crust has a really
nice crunch.
I can't really tell that
it's gluten-free,
'cause it tastes really,
really good.
How do we
start to make it?
CHAD: We got our
pizza-flour mix.
It's a gluten-free
flour that you buy?
Yes.
Okay.
And so what do you got in there?
You got rice, potato.
Tapioca
and then brown rice.
So, this is just
our Italian seasoning.
Salt.
Okay.
Olive oil, eggs,
our gluten-free beer
to get some carbonation...
Okay.
...and activated yeast.
Then we let that go
for about a minute,
put it in a bowl,
and let it proof
for about an hour.
And we're going
to parbake it.
This looks like the hubcap
from "Cobra."
Remember when
Sylvester Stallone...
Sly, are these yours?
What we're going to do is
spread it out with a spatula.
Look at this little
feathering technique you have.
You got to give it
a little bit of an edge.
I like it!
There we go.
And then we're going to pop it
right in the oven.
And what temperature
are we running that?
550,
3 or 4 minutes.
A little bit of crust
to it. Wow.
Now we're going to
make our sausage
for our
Paradise Pesto Pizza.
WOMAN: I love
the Paradise Pesto Pizza.
The sausage is absolutely
delicious.
So, what we're going
to do now is just make
the seasoning blend.
Got it.
Got our paprika,
ground pepper,
Himalayan pink sea salt,
and Italian seasoning,
garlic powder,
chili powder,
ground-up fennel.
A lot of it.
Nice little dry rub
put together.
Now our pork.
Start hitting this
with a little dry rub?
Yep, perfect.
All right.
So this goes in the cooler
24 hours, and we bring it out,
you grind it,
and this is all going
for the Paradise...
Pesto Pizza.
Pesto is last?
Yep.
So what we got is our basil
we grow here,
macadamia nuts,
chopped-up garlic,
Himalayan salt, ground pepper,
lemon juice, olive oil.
♪♪
We gonna
put this together?
Yep.
First off, our pesto that
we just made,
big old handful
of cheese.
It's a mozzarella/provolone
blend.
That's a lot of cheese.
Pepperoncinis, sweet onions,
artichoke hearts, olives.
Kalamatas?
Exactly.
Some of the sausage
we just ground up
and then just a nice
little sprinkle of feta.
How long is that gonna
go in the oven?
About 6, 7 minutes.
♪♪
Fresh Parmesan.
Looks like pizza,
smells like pizza.
♪♪
You can see right here
how thin that is,
just a little bit of dough,
great texture.
No question -- your toppings
are fantastic,
your sauce is great,
the pesto is really on point.
I think if you gave this
to the average person,
they wouldn't know
this was gluten-free dough.
That's exactly
what I was going for.
Really good, man.
Thank you.
MAN: Paradise Pesto.
The sausage on top
is flavorful and savory.
MAN: I love this pesto.
It's made with macadamia nuts,
so it really pops.
Can you get a Teriyaki Chicken
Bowl started for me?
TERRY: I sure can.
Are the guests that
you're getting in
looking for
gluten-free food?
I'd say about 70%.
Someone in their group.
FIERI: Which includes
49ers Hall of Famer Steve Young,
who's a regular here
since his wife is gluten-free.
YOUNG: This is the oasis
in the desert.
This is like looking off
and seeing some mirage,
like,
"Is it really true?"
We overeat every single
time we come here.
CHAD: I got the fish and chips
coming at you.
MAN:
Fish and chips, I love.
They're very crispy
on the outside
but yet fall apart
on the inside.
Now we're going to make
fish and chips
because most fish and chips
are not gluten-free.
Not at all.
Let's get into it.
We got to make the batter --
gluten-free all-purpose flour,
garlic powder,
chili powder,
baking powder,
ground black pepper,
Himalayan salt,
and a little paprika.
And then in with
the beer.
Do you sell gluten-free
beer here, as well?
We do.
So, we got our walu
from a local provider.
And then dredge it in.
Fry it up.
Beer-battered onion rings
will be in the same batter.
All right, chef.
Let's see it.
♪♪
[ Chuckles ]
What's the verdict?
That is the lightest,
crunchiest breading I've had.
I mean, that's
the crunch you want.
That's crazy.
Dude...
This is better than the majority
of onion rings I've had.
It is light,
it is not that heavy,
fried-batter feeling.
Cool.
I mean, that's it.
Every time I go
get fish and chips,
I'm gonna ask
for gluten-free.
[ Laughs ]
All right, Dad,
I got fish and chips.
MAN: Awesome fish.
You can tell everything
is locally taught.
WOMAN: Something about
the types of flours
they use and stuff --
it just is so good.
It's crunchier
and lighter.
And then the inside
is so much moister.
Excellent food,
excellent service.
SERVER: And your
pepperoni-and-cheese pizza.
MAN: Really great people.
They take care of you.
You have to come
and see this place.
As a young chef,
you have done a fantastic job
to debunk the funk
of gluten-free.
This has
been a pleasure.
Thank you, sir.
Proud of you.
Nice job.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Virginia Beach...
Ca-la-la-ga-
la-a-a-a-a!
...a chef dishing out
his mama's island secrets...
Funkalicious
deliciousness.
...with his own
special flair.
You can't
miss this one.
♪♪
I'm here in Virginia Beach,
on Shore Drive,
and the place
I'm checking out,
the owner's supposed
to be a true character.
The restaurant is
in an office building,
and the food
is supposed to taste
like it comes
right from the islands.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is it -- Carib Shack.
♪♪
Rice Curry Chicken Bowl.
A little slice of the islands
in a strip mall.
Cocoa beef.
There's a lot of love
and time and effort put into it.
Putting the rice down
for the curry bowls.
There's obviously amazing food,
but the family atmosphere
is maybe
the best part about it.
FIERI: That family feel
comes from family ties
with owner Vinny Gagliani,
his sister, and his girlfriend
all serving up
his mom's Caribbean recipes.
I used to watch her cook,
growing up,
for my sister
and myself.
In 2014, they traded their
Virgin Islands for Virginia
and, less than a year later,
opened up this joint.
How do you describe
island cuisine?
It's all fused,
you know,
the blend of cultures
over the years.
It's a lot of
slow-cooking...
Yes.
...taking tougher
pieces of meat,
stewing them,
braising them.
SERVER:
Shack Jerk Pork Bowl.
MAN: The jerk pork is some
of the best pork
I've ever had
in my entire life.
It's really spicy.
It's got a good kick to it.
What are we gonna make?
We're going to make
our marinade for our
Shack Jerk Pork Bowl.
Shack Jerk Pork Bowl?
Sherk Jack Perk --
Different language.
I'll translate for you.
Fire away.
Orange juice, lime juice,
oil, cilantro, mint,
basil, oregano,
Italian parsley,
thyme, our orange zest.
We've got
some lime zest...
Garlic.
...cumin, salt, and pepper.
Dude, you are in Herb City
right here.
Yes, sir.
Boneless pork butt.
I like the beginning
of this deal.
And how long is this pork butt
gonna sit here
in this funkalicious
deliciousness?
Overnight.
That's crazy.
And how are we going to cook
the meat after we're done?
Put it in an oven at 425.
Okay, Vincenzo,
what are we up to?
We're going to make
our jerk barbecue sauce.
Okay.
We'll use
our house-made ketchup.
Someone got a little
wild with the cinnamon
today, didn't they?
Oh, yeah.
Maybe a touch
of nutmeg.
Oh, yeah.
And some allspice too.
Couldn't tell.
Couldn't tell, huh?
Couldn't tell
it was in there.
We got our brown sugar,
some molasses,
apple cider vinegar,
mustard.
Okay.
Only 25 things
going in this.
Cayenne,
onion powder...
Got it.
...garlic, smoked paprika,
Worcestershire sauce.
What was it called?
Worcest-sha-
sha-sha sauce.
Black pepper and salt.
A little bit of water to get
a little viscosity going.
While this is getting hot
and the sugar's dissolving,
we're going to make
our jerk seasoning.
Okay.
Start with our onions,
scallions, thyme,
pimiento peppers...
Okay.
...roasted Scotch
bonnet peppers.
Whoa!
I almost popped one
of those into my mouth.
"Hey!
Look, a peppadew."
Garlic, salt.
There we go.
♪♪
Now we're going to add
the jerk seasoning.
And that's the sauce
that we're going to
cook the pork with?
Yes.
We slice it up.
Pork's cubed up.
Yep.
Heat that up.
Get nice and crunchy.
Then we add
our jerk barbecue.
Now we're going to put it
in our Shack Jerk Pork Bowl.
We're going to start out
with the pigeon peas and rice
cooked in coconut milk,
cabbage and carrots
steamed down,
and then, finally, we add
the jerk pork.
You don't skimp on the sauce,
now, do you, Hoss?
Uh, no.
So if I go to Saint Thomas,
I go to the island,
this is something similar
to what I'm going to find?
Yep.
You got to
make sure you got
the party
going on first, though.
You got to get
the party going on?
Yeah.
You get the party going on.
I'm gonna have this.
♪♪
I knew he would do it.
I knew he'd do it.
♪ One love... ♪
[ Laughs ]
Okay, enough, man.
♪ One love... ♪
Enough, enough.
[ Laughs ]
Whoa!
That jerk barbecue sauce
in there just by itself
has got some kick.
♪♪
The mild carrots and cabbage
coming together
with the peas and rice,
when you get that combo bite,
then it starts
to really get this...
balance, you know?
It's a really hearty bowl.
The marinade is out of bounds.
I'd eat this
all day long, bro.
All day long.
Thank you.
Like, real legit.
Mmm.
SERVER:
Shack Jerk Pork Bowl.
The Jerk Pork Bowl
is delicious.
Nice, big chunks of pork.
It's very good.
MAN: I've spent some time
in the Navy,
did a lot of port calls
down in the Caribbean.
The first time I walked in here
instantly brought me back.
MAN: Great personality
when you come in here.
It's a cool
hole-in-the-wall.
Oh, that's
not even a wall.
GAGLIANI: No.
It's cardboard.
And you decorated this
with paper...
Yep.
...that you
glued to the wall.
69 cents apiece.
[ Italian accent ]
69 cents apiece!
Yeah!
I like the way this guy works.
He's got his own style.
Two jerk pork bowls,
curry bowl, Cuban Calypso.
Today.
[ Laughter ]
It's friendly, it's fresh
it's beautifully made.
So, here's the deal -- we're
hanging out at the Carib Shack.
When you come back,
another great dish
cooked in a very simple kitchen
by Vinny, the man himself.
SERVER:
Mama's Beef Bowl.
The stew beef is rich,
it's delicious.
MAN: The beef literally melts
in your mouth.
Flavors are incredible.
Y'all come back, now,
you hear?
Come back. Come back.
Come back. Please.
Please, come on back.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back, everybody,
in Food Network Land.
We're here at
the Carib Shack,
and we're going to cook
some food with --
What's your name, again?
I'm the host.
Oh, yeah.
Vinny, I'm the host
of the show.
Yes, yes, yes.
We're at the Carib Shack
in Virginia.
This guy is
a piece of work.
The food's great, but come down
for the floor show.
WOMAN: It's like a little slice
of the Caribbean
here in Virginia Beach.
MAN: Vinny's got
his great family recipes
that he puts
a lot of love into.
All right. What's up, buddy?
What are we making next?
We're going to make
our Mama's Stew Beef Bowl.
We're going to use
our Angus chuck beef.
Make it nice.
We cube this up, you know.
[ As Borat ] Make it nice!
Make it nice!
Add our house ketchup,
green seasoning.
[ Normal voice ]
Green seasoning.
We make it with cilantro,
scallions,
garlic, you know,
thyme.
Got it.
Garlic powder,
onion powder,
S&P -- salt and pepper.
Oh, look at you
just throwing out
all the culinary
nomenclature.
There you go.
Mix this together
and then cook it in a pot?
Yep.
We add oil.
We're gonna get
some sugar in there
to get it nice
and caramelized.
So sugar, too?
Now you can start
dropping the meat.
Drop it like it's...
Drop it like --
Hot?
There you go.
You're late on that.
So, we brown it up, and then
we're going to add the water?
Yeah.
Now we're going to let
it simmer for an hour.
Vinny, what are we doing?
We got soaked lentils.
Yep.
We're gonna make the lentils
for the Mama's Stew Beef Bowl.
The first thing is oil
and house-made ketchup.
Calabaza pumpkin.
Ca-la-la-ga-
la-a-a-a-a!
Carrots.
The green sauce,
green seasoning.
Garlic powder,
onion powder.
Got it.
Garlic,
salt, and pepper.
And then the soaked lentils,
water and all.
Water and all.
Cook this down
for about 45 minutes.
So, you're going to take it,
pull it out, puree it,
throw it back in.
Yep.
And then
it'll be ready?
Yep.
Okay.
So, we're going to plate
our Mama's Stew Beef Bowl.
Pigeon peas and rice,
the stewed lentils, stewed beef.
♪♪
That's tasty lentils.
Nice, simple protein.
Boy,
that beef is tender.
The lentils, to me, are
the real hit of the whole deal,
and they
really carry it.
But, boy, it's good.
Thank you.
The food and the attitude
and the style and smile
on the face of this place
says "Island."
SERVER:
Mama's Beef Bowl.
So many different
dynamic flavors.
A lot of time and care
has gone into that dish.
It's very comforting.
So, it's like, to come in
and get all this flavor
is what
keeps you coming back.
Bye, everybody,
in Food TV Land.
[ Laughs ]
Goodbye to Vinny.
He might leave with me.
You're not
getting in the car.
No.
No, I wont.
I'm serious.
Don't get in the car.
I might be
in the trunk.
Not in the trunk, Vinny.
You're not coming.
You stay here.
I might be
in the trunk, though.
Well done, brother.
Thank you.
Thank you very much
for having me.
You can't
miss this one.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
but don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over the country.
I'll catch you next time
on "Triple D."
♪♪
Is there more kitchen?
Is there a kitchen downstairs?
I'm going to
go down and check.
[ Laughter ]
There's nothing
down there!