Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
This trip,
Och, yes!
we're loadin' up...
Bring the kids down
for Thanksgiving.
[ Laughs]
pilin' up...
You don't stop, do ya?
and fillin' up in Flavortown.
That is ridunculous.
That means skyscraper sandwiches
at a Palm Desert deli...
I'm just startin'
to drool.
...a potato paradise
in Orlando.
You've just crushed it.
...along with
decked-out dogs...
You start building 'em,
I'm gonna start eating 'em.
...fired up by a famous face.
One more, breathe.
[patting Fieri's back]
Can I go walk it off?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here
in the Palm Springs area --
actually, Palm Desert,
to be exact --
and, last year, I was here
for an awesome concert
and I fell into the same trap
everybody does.
I came to a town
a hadn't been to
and I didn't know where to eat.
Wasn't gonna let
that happened again,
so I rolled in "Triple D"-style,
found one of the greats.
This is Sherman's Deli.
♪♪
Order in.
Two latke pastramis.
This is a staple of great
food in Palm Desert.
Drop and kraut
on the grill.
It's very representative of
the best delis in the country.
-Table 2!
-It's definitely
a landmark in the area.
So popular, founder
Sherman Harris got his own spot
on the Walk of Stars
in Palm Springs,
where he originally
opened in 1963.
Now daughter Janet and son Sam
are pickin' up where
their late father left off...
Sam and Janet have done
an amazing job.
They're actually
growing the legacy.
...adding this second location
of Palm Desert and expanding
the menu with new hits,
like this twist from longtime
chef Gordon Poster.
POSTER:
Two turkey pastramis.
The turkey pastrami
is a family favorite.
The rye bread's fresh,
lot of flavor to it.
We make all of our rye
here in-house
and we do it to 100-plus
loaves a day.
-Seriously?
-Absolutely.
Let's see it, man.
We're just gonna
start off with water.
Not regular warm water,
ice water.
-No, we go for the cold factor.
-Okay.
Then we're gonna start off
with clear flour.
It's a little bit finer
than regular all-purpose flour.
-Got it.
-Thai gluten flour.
Then we've got what's called
whole rye flour, actually.
-Whole rye flour.
-And this is called a rye base.
What this is,
this actually has the sugar,
little bit of the salt,
all the active ingredients
that's gonna ignite the yeast.
We actually have it shipped
in from New York.
And we're gonna throw
the yeast right on top of that.
-A bunch of yeast.
-Vegetable shortening.
-And than a ton of -- wow!
-Ton of caraway.
And did we toast those
or anything,
or is it just --?
-No, these are straight up
because they're gonna
toast in with the bread
and you want to get all that raw
flavor coming right out of it.
How long is this
gonna knead for?
About 10 minutes.
-All right, Chef, let's see it.
-Take this thing out,
then we're gonna cut it
into 2 pounds, 12 ounces.
Every day, it's a routine
that you're making bread?
We start off at about
5:00 at night.
We get it done,
so first thing in the morning,
they've had a chance to rest
and we're ready to go
rock 'n' roll on it.
And we leave it a little bit
on the wet stage.
-To attract the cornmeal.
-Absolutely.
We want the cornmeal
to rest right into it.
How does it smell
when you come in here
in the morning?
-Pheno-me-nal.
Oh!
My mouth, I'm just
startin' to drool.
So we'll let this go
in the proof
for 45 minutes?
-Correct.
And then we're gonna
bake it off at...?
405 degrees
for about 30 minutes.
-405?
-405 degrees.
-Not 404?
-No.
Not 406?
We set the thermostat
at 405.
405. All right,
let's get into it.
Turkey pastrami.
We've got 1/2 gallon of water.
This is salt.
So we got equal parts
of salt and sugar.
-Absolutely. But we use
the brown sugar,
because we want the molasses.
Then we're gonna use
whole garlic.
-Whole cloves.
-Ton of bay leaves.
-Juniper berries.
-That's the key to it.
That's it.
And then we got dried thyme.
We're steeping this brine,
letting all these flavors
come together.
And how long is this turkey
gonna brine
in this
fantastic mixture?
-24 hours.
-Really?
Look at this.
This is absolutely beautiful.
Now what's our dry rub
gonna be?
We've got the juniper
right there;
we got the peppercorns here,
and we put a little bit
of the fresh coriander.
I love fresh coriander.
Pulse it a few times
and then you get this really,
really nice rub,
which is great.
Now we have it covered.
Wrap it up, 24 hours,
then we're gonna go
to the oven and --
No, we're gonna go
to the smoker.
Going to the smoker with this?
You don't stop, do ya?
-No, I don't.
-How many hours
are in your day,
-Not enough.
-25?
-At least.
This is the rye. We cut it.
Look at that crust.
-Huh? Huh?
-Isn't that great?
[Singer performs ethereal tune]
Och!
There is so much
caraway in that.
The cornmeal crust
just crushes it.
Give him privacy.
It is so good.
♪♪
And this is how
we pile 'em up here?
We use 1/2 pound
of meat for every sandwich.
1/2 pound of meat.
♪♪
That...
is...really good.
-Thank you.
-It's cut thick.
You just get a little bit
of that allspice bite,
little bit of that
pepper in the back.
I'm definitely
getting the coriander.
Perfectly cooked.
You can see
how it's nice and tender,
but it's moist.
Ohh! If that's
the only thing
that you sold here,
-[Laughing]
I could expect lines
all the way
to Wisconsin.
♪♪
It's really
outstanding.
Very good, very tasty.
The turkey has
a wonderful smoky quality.
Just the right amount
of caraway
and that cornmeal
makes the crust
so crunchy
and delicious.
If this was the only thing
that we're gonna show you
of Sherman's, it'd be worth it
to come down today right now.
But, you got more up
your sleeve, don't you?
Absolutely. We've got
a beautiful latke
and a brisket that's gonna
knock your socks off.
WOMAN:
Beef and latkes.
A sandwich of latkes
with beef in the middle.
Just melts in your mouth.
We're hangin' out
in Palm Desert with the chef,
the man that made
the bomb turkey pastrami.
When we come back,
it's latkes, it's brisket,
and I'll be asleep in booth 10.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We are at Sherman's
in Palm Desert
with the Wise One.
That would be
Chef Gordon Poster,
who's servin' up oldschool
Jewish deli greats.
I love all the variety.
They give you
a lot of food.
WOMAN:
Turkey sandwich on rye.
I've slowed down.
-I'm not done, though.
-I -- don't do any more to me.
I can't --
Okay, go ahead.
Latkes and brisket, sir.
Their latkes are just
about the biggest latkes
I've ever had, and their
brisket is the best.
Now we're gonna do
our brisket of beef.
We're gonna add our mirepoix.
Gonna put the onions,
got a little bit
of celery going on here,
and we put the carrots.
Nice, beautiful,
big, fat brisket.
Gonna just hit it
with a little salt and pepper.
Don't rinse the seasoning
off the top.
-Oh, no.
-Foil?
-No, I do not use foil.
-No?
We like to get
that crusty on the top.
-To the oven.
-Approximately 3.5 to 4 hours.
We're gonna make the latkes
for our beef and latke dish.
-Okay. Hit it.
-Start off with our fresh,
shredded potatoes.
We're gonna add the water.
Here's the tricky part.
I want you to take
a whiff of this.
Tell me what you think
that is.
Has it got a citrus to it
or what is it?
Sour salt is
dehydrated citric acid.
Aha! It did have
a citrus. Okay.
Absolutely. So we're gonna
put that in here.
We just stir it around.
-And what is that going to do?
Well, you know, like we use
vinegar or we use lemon juice
to keep it?
It's the same thing,
but the sour salt
gives it a little flavor,
a little punch to it.
-A little tang.
Absolutely.
We're gonna add the onions.
Just some of 'em.
We're just gonna add
a little bit of onions.
-A few of the onions.
-Then we're gonna take this
all out
and we're gonna drain it.
This is all right
back in the pot.
Now we add the rest
of our onions.
Okay.
And just throw that around.
We're gonna sprinkle
some flour in there.
-Black pepper, granulated onion.
-Onion?
And regular table salt.
You don't want to use
the kosher, 'cause it's too big.
-Right.
-You want to be able to have
that real fine product
that's getting into it.
Then we pour our eggs in.
Fold it a little bit
at a time.
You're treatin' it
like meatballs.
Absolutely.
You don't want to overwork it,
because there's still liquid
in the potato, it starts
forming its batter.
So we got it all ready,
just enough to bind it.
There's enough flour coating it;
-I gotcha.
there's enough egg.
-This is regular
vegetable shortening that we do
in a pan and keep it shallow.
What we do is we just
kind of like fold it up,
let it go for a couple
of minutes.
Then when they get
nice and brown,
then we're gonna turn 'em over.
-Okay.
It's gonna be a little bit
of soft on the inside;
the outside's gonna
have a nice crunch to it.
All right, here's the latkes,
nice and fresh.
Look at these things.
Wait, you could hide
behind this. The bank
robber was wearing a latke.
His accomplice...
-Wears the other latke.
[laughing] And they
had armed themselves
with a pruning knife.
[ Laughing helplessly ]
Oh, this is incredible.
I love this.
Nice and steamy.
-There we go.
You let that crust
build up
and really let
that fat render down.
Oh! Yes!
We're gonna cut it
and, again,
1/2 pound.
-Yes, of course.
Then we just take this.
No one person
can eat all that.
They do, but we have to
walk 'em outside
and then they don't have a meal
for the rest of the day.
What is that little dressing
that you gave me?
That is creamy
horseradish sauce.
Ahhh!
-There's the hunch. Come on.
Oh, you know the hunch?!
I know the hunch.
Impressed!
Crunchy latke,
and the meat,
and the bomb
horseradish cream,
all together
in every bite.
I'm not hangin' out
with you anymore.
Nah.
Not unless you got
a treadmill at home.
Dude, I'm gonna
take the floorboard
out of the Camaro
and just
[ Scampering ]
"Yabba Dabba Doo" it
home.
You're a bad man.
Mmm.
WOMAN:
Beef and latkes.
I've never seen
anything like it before.
It's very unique
to Sherman's.
The potatoes were crisp;
the beef is fantastic.
FIERI:
But locals say no trip
to Sherman's is complete
[chuckle] without dessert.
That bakery,
it's like a wonderland.
Look at this thing.
Make all the desserts in-house?
-We do.
-And we bake 24 hours a day.
As a kid,
I loved the bakery.
That was something
I always looked forward to.
-What is the best dessert?
-Banana tart.
And I've had almost every single
dessert on the menu.
Really?
I always look forward
to coming to Sherm's.
One Philly cheese,
one Reuben stacker.
MAN:
It's a great restaurant.
Flavor is just
spectacular.
I've questioned if I would
ever find a place
like this
on the West Coast
and I found a couple.
This is a gem.
No wonder you guys have
been doing it since '63.
Outstanding, man.
-Thank you.
Outstanding.
Comin' up...
I'm hooking up
with some buddies in Orlando...
We're the triple threat.
And none of us
like to eat.
...to hit a unique
Brazilian spot.
It's a rock concert.
It's delicious.
...all about proppin'
up potatoes.
This is like
the Potato Institute.
...which is a good thing.
Now we're gonna load it up
with a heapin'
helpin' of hospitality.
We can do about 4 tons
of brisket a year.
8,000 pounds
of brisket,
-Mm-hmm.
at 1/2 pound
per serving,
-Correct.
-That's gotta be
7 billion people.
That's good.
-It works.
[ Beep ]
♪♪
So I'm here in wonderful
Orlando, Florida,
with good friends
Joey Fatone and Robert Earl.
Robert's the founder
of Planet Hollywood.
And well, you know Joey
from TV, movies, and, well,
a little group called NSYNC.
-Are you gonna let him out?
-No.
We're here to check out
a joint --
[English accent]
Joey, please, let me out!
We're here to check out
a joint where a Brazilian chef
is servin' up nothing
but potatoes.
This is Mrs. Potato.
Joey, let him out.
-All right, all right.
♪♪
I love the food.
Carne-seca Rosti,
7 more minutes.
Potatoes are a very
traditional food in Brazil.
It brings us a little bit
back to our root.
FIERI:
Which is exactly the reason
behind Rafaela Cabede's
potato palace.
She moved to the US
from Brazil as a kid
and when she decided
to open a restaurant,
she had one question.
"What do I miss from home
that I can't get here?"
and then it clicked.
My potatoes.
So you're Mrs. Potato.
We're the Three Amigos.
-We're the triple threat.
And none of us
like to eat.
Luckily, her signature
specialty comes in XL.
Carne-seca Rosti up!
Let me tell you,
it's the biggest hash brown
you ever seen.
And you can add whatever
filling you want to it.
So what are we gonna start with?
-Carne seca.
FIERI:
Which dried beef,
big in Brazil.
-This is top butt.
-Okay.
-And we salt it.
-To pull a lot of moisture out.
Do you think you
put enough salt in?
I think it's snowing
in that pot.
It goes into the fridge
for three days.
So we're gonna eat
in about four days.
-Cool. I love it.
-[Laughing]
So now we're gonna rinse
it four or five times.
Then it goes into
the pressure cooker.
45 minutes to an hour.
We just pull the meat and shred
it and that's the beginning.
Yes.
We are gonna do
the seasoning.
Got onion, garlic.
Tomatoes.
Look at that.
So if that doesn't
smell fantastic,
you have got serious problems.
-Amazing.
Now we're gonna
add the cilantro.
♪ Cilantro ♪
I love that song!
Now we are making
the roast beef.
So, shredded potato.
Seasoned with salt
and pepper.
-Okay.
-Then we add the filling,
then we top it
with some more potatoes.
It goes to the stove.
We get some oil.
-So how long does this go?
-6 minutes on each side.
Tell me about this place
that we're going after this.
-It's close.
-But you're not gonna tell me
where it is?
-You're gonna love it.
Okay.
So now
we're flipping it.
-Oo-ooh.
-Ahhh.
Lookin' great.
Rosti toasty, I do say!
So this is Catupiry.
It's a Brazilian
cream cheese.
Dried parsley.
-FIERI: Okay.
And these are
pimenta biquinho.
It's a pepper
from Brazil.
It actually
has no heat at all,
but it has
a lot of flavor.
[ Laughter ]
-Tasty.
-Here is our carne-seca Rosti.
Gentlemen, here it is.
The moment is here.
It's quiet,
all of a sudden.
[ Whimsical tune plays ]
[ Rock music plays ]
FIERI:
It's really good.
I want like
10 of these to go.
[Laughing]
I wanna have a house party.
I could see why people
can eat the whole thing.
It is moist,
the cheese seems
to really entwine
with the potato
and with the meat.
It's excellent!
I was worried there's
just not enough
phenomenal ingredients for it
to get all
the reputation it's got.
But you jut made music
with a stringed tin can.
-EARL: Bravo!
I mean, it's just --
it's a rock concert.
It's delicious.
Carne seca, 2 minutes!
It's crispy and also
very smooth.
You can't stop eating.
It's terrific.
Start working on pastel!
Rafaela is
an amazing person.
She worked hard to be
where she is now.
-Come on.
-But if this is work,
boy, does she make it
look like play.
-All the hips.
-Well, I got a lot of hip.
FIERI:
And she puts
all that big energy
right into more
super-sized servings.
Here is the chicken-Catupiry
baked potato.
The chicken-Catupiry
baked potato
is one of everybody's
favorite food in here.
It's out of the world.
-What are we making next?
-The chicken-Catupiry.
So here we got
some raw chicken, water.
Paprika.
Celery salt, salt,
garlic powder,
complete seasoning.
What is complete seasoning?
A mix,
especially for Latin.
-Like adobo?
-Yes.
Bay leaves.
-Okay.
It cooks for 25
to 30 minutes.
Let it cool, shred that meat.
-Mm-hmm.
Very nice.
So these are the monsters
that you make?
Giant Idaho potatoes.
How do you say?
Jacked potato?
Jacket potato.
It's inside its jacket.
Coat them with oil,
you get salt,
450 degrees for about
1 hour and 20 minutes.
Okay, hit it.
-We have the chicken
and then this is
cream cheese; heavy cream.
-Got it.
-And then --
EARL:
Oh, we like this.
-Catupiry!
-Look at that.
Three dairy products.
Now what you have
at this point, gentlemen,
is phenomenal
chicken salad.
-So we have the baked potato.
-So, wait, what is this?
-This is butter with
-Little compound butter.
garlic, salt,
and dried parsley.
You want to try it
like this?
Oh, my goodness.
We are seeing the indulgence.
This is an incredible
side, just as-is.
Now we're gonna load it up
with a heapin'
helpin' of hospitality.
Here we have mozzarella
and Provolone.
Bring the whole
football team down.
And we're gonna pop
this in the oven
just to melt the cheese.
[laughing]
Robert is ready.
We are commencing
readiness, yes.
♪♪
[ Laughing ]
That is ridunculous.
Mmm!
It's about
four days of food.
I can --
There you go.
Joey.
You're taking the simple potato
that a lot of people don't give
a lot of time and respect to
-Yeah.
and you're going
above and beyond
the cheese.
-That is awesome.
This is like
the Potato Institute.
You've just crushed it.
Nice job.
Chicken-Catupiry
baked potato!
If you eat the whole potato,
then you better
hibernate for a while.
That's amazing.
Ham-and-cheese Rosti
going down!
I love it. You can't ask
for anything better.
Sister,
this is really fantastic.
-Thank you.
To have a restaurant
that has dishes
that no one else has,
-No one else has.
-this is special.
-Gimme a hug.
-Ahh! Now we're talking.
See, it's so beautiful,
I'm -- See, I'm tearing up.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
-Huh? The bomb, or what?
-Unbelievable.
-I told you.
-Would've never known.
All right,
where are we goin' next?
Just follow me.
It's pretty simple.
-Oh, we're taking your car?
-No, actually, I'm gonna drive
with your car
and gimme the keys.
-[sighing] Oh.
-Come on.
Fatone, this better
be worth it.
It's gonna be
worth it.
You know, if I were
a bettin' man,
I'd say we could be
headed to the dogs.
Oh, gosh.
This is not
for the faint of heart.
After the break.
-[Laughing]
♪♪
Joey, you brought me
to a mall.
Yeah, a mall. It's the
home of the Fat One.
-The Fat One?
-Yeah, Fat One.
As in you?
As in, you'll see.
You'll love it.
♪♪
All right, buddy,
this is it, Fat One's.
My joint.
Turns out, Joey Fatone
is a Coney Island kid turned
bona fide food fanatic,
so he decided
to start servin' up
two of his childhood
favorites:
Italian ice...
-That's cotton candy.
Wow, dude. That tastes
just like cotton candy.
...and hot dogs.
Obviously, Joey's from New York.
You can tell it in his menu.
You're gonna get that New York
style that snaps in your mouth.
It's great.
When you brought me here,
I thought it was just like
a little hot-dog stand,
but this is a full-blown like
little mini-restaurant
in the middle of a mall.
-Oh, yeah.
-All right,
you start building 'em,
I'm gonna start eating 'em.
-Perfect.
♪♪
All right, this one is
a Gone Hollywood.
There's mozzarella cheese,
guacamole, and diced tomatoes.
Everybody loves avocado.
Joey puts avocado in it
and all of a sudden,
it's a health-food snack.
Have you eaten avocado
with a hot dog before, though?
Dude, a legit dog.
You treat the bun
with respect.
-We try.
-That's a big deal.
Yeah, no.
We like to toast the buns.
100% beef.
FIERI:
And butterfly.
I like when you
split it open.
You get tons
of texture.
Give a little more
flavor to it?
The beauty part about that is,
is, too, the reason
why we butterfly it,
is you can fit more of
the stuff inside it.
Meaning like it won't
fall completely over.
All right, bring me
another one.
-All right.
-I'm gonna die.
This is the Mac Daddy.
We got the bacon,
we got white-cheddar
mac 'n' cheese.
-There's mac 'n' cheese.
-Spirals.
-It's mac 'n' cheese. Mac Daddy.
♪♪
Really good
mac 'n' cheese.
-Great. Don't eat more.
-I really like that one, though.
Now then, what we do different
with these, these are pressed.
-Okay.
-So we do a Reuben and a Cuban.
This one is the Cuban.
Obviously, pickles.
It's got the mustard.
That's really good.
The pressing of the sandwich
makes the whole thing.
-Who designed all the recipes?
-I did.
Me and two, three other people
came up with different ideas.
I got one more for ya.
One more.
Breathe. [patting Fieri's back]
-Can I go walk it off?
FATONE:
Now this is the Fat One.
The Fat One, it's the
kitchen-sink dog,
where you
get everything on it.
This has nacho cheese,
sweet [laughing] onions,
mozzarella. We got corn beef;
we got French fries.
-There's pepperoni in it?
-Yep.
[ Laughing ]
Bring the kids down
for Thanksgiving.
[ Laughing ]
-Wow.
-It's not for the
faint of heart.
-And, obviously, the flavor
-Wow.
punches out a lot more,
'cause that's the Angus beef.
It's the 16 pounds
of pepperoni.
[ Laughing ]
And the extra French fry
that you wedged inside.
Well, you know, just like
everything, you want something
that's gonna be a staple.
[laughing]
Uh.
Dude, I'm really impressed.
-Thank you.
You did way more
than rubber-stamp this
with Joey Fatone's name.
-Tryin'. Thank you,
thank you, thank you.
Legit as can be.
♪♪
Most hot-dog places, you don't
have that crisp bite.
This one's perfect.
I dig it.
I know your customers do.
But I have got a tasting panel,
well, they'll tell me the truth.
Are they like
culinary like --
Well, they've been
to every "Triple D" joint
that I've been to, so,
-All right.
so let's see what
the camera crew thinks.
♪♪
[ Ding! ]
It's worth a special trip
to Florida Mall.
You're gonna get a unique dog
like you've never had before.
It's awesome.
FIERI:
And the name
can't be any funnier.
It's my last name, split.
Fat One.
Perfect, dude. The best
play of name ever.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry,
there's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be lookin'
for you next week,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
It goes into
the pressure cooker.
♪ Pressure cooker ♪
[ Laughter ]
♪ Meat in the bucket ♪
EARL: Yes!
[Electricity buzzing]
[Cackling]