I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Get it.
...we're eating
the extraordinary...
There is nothing
I don't love about this.
...at places
that aren't so ordinary...
Every time you're supposed
to take a right, you went left.
...like a seafood shack
in Cancun...
That's exactly
what I wanted.
...that's simple in the front,
but party in the back.
It is a funky,
little, cool hideout.
And check out
this Houston spot...
That's got all
my favorite flavors.
...serving a surprising spin
on surf and turf.
If you put barbecue
and sushi together,
it better
taste like that.
...and a Charlotte beer store,
plus wild waffles...
Yes, I'll
bring one home.
...equals a funkalicious
find in Flavortown.
Man, you have
rocked the house.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
You can't come to Charlotte,
North Carolina,
without coming to NoDa,
North of Davidson.
You know we've been here
before -- Cabo Fish Taco.
Anyhow, I got a really
interesting one.
See, this guy's
got a beer shop.
And then he talks
to his other buddy,
who wants to open a restaurant.
They say, "Great, let's blow
a hole through the wall."
Well, and the rest is history.
This is FuD At Salud.
McELWEE:
Order up. Frambella.
Absolutely a hidden gem.
All right,
I have waffles rancheros.
What's the level of the food
in your opinion?
Holy smoke.
This stuff's incredible.
And it's unique.
Michelle O'Banh Mi,
table three.
Jeff is creating big,
brilliant things back there.
That's owner Jeff McElwee,
who's making up for
a lack of formal training
with loads of imagination.
Were you always like
this as a kid -- inquisitive
and just doing things your way
and making things happen?
Yeah.
So, when buddy Jason Glunt
was looking to serve food
at his bottle shop,
Jeff could picture
the opportunity.
He saw somewhere doing
peanut butter-and-jelly waffles.
Like, "That's kind of boring.
Let's get weird with it."
Four waffles up.
Four waffles going down.
FIERI: So, now he's serving up
a whole line
of wild waffle sandwiches.
You're Killin' Me,
S'Mores.
Okay, what are we
making, dude?
All right. So, making
our homemade waffle batter.
It's for the You're Killin'
Me S'Mores waffle-wich.
Waffle batter
with egg whites?
Damn right.
Meringue.
Get it.
Oh, yeah.
We start off
with egg yolks, sugar.
And we're gonna beat
enough air into it
that it's gonna go
from yellow to bright white.
We're gonna add our butter
nice and slow
so it doesn't
shoot everywhere.
Cut the speed down
to about two.
Grab our vanilla,
toss that in there.
How many waffles
will this make?
I wouldn't say tons,
but definitely a lot.
Right in the middle.
Yeah.
Leaning towards tons?
Honestly, I haven't
looked into it that much.
You're gonna
have to study.
All right.
So, then we're gonna
grab our milk.
Whole milk.
You want that fat.
We're tossing
our salt in there.
Throwing the baking
powder in there.
Okay.
Cornstarch.
What?
Well, they called
for cake flour.
Cake flour is
cornstarch and flour.
So, we grab
our sifted flour.
Now we're gonna beat it
till it's smooth.
So, now we're gonna
add our batter mixture
into our meringue,
and then just fold it in
till it's smooth.
Nice folding.
Thanks, man.
Thanks for noticing.
The waffle maker's hot.
Cook it
for three minutes.
Next step?
Making the marshmallows.
If you're gonna
sell s'mores indoors,
you got to make
the marshmallows.
For sures.
For sures when
the s'more's indoors.
Yeah.
Start off
with water, gelatin.
Got it.
While that's mixing,
we're gonna start
adding our ingredients
to our saucepan.
Water. Corn syrup.
Salt.
Finally --
Copious amounts of sugar.
Yeah, that's copious.
Once this guy gets boiling,
we're gonna transfer it.
Add it nice and slow.
It's 240 degrees,
and it will hurt pretty good.
Mix, mix, mix?
Yeah.
About 10 minutes into it,
we're gonna add our vanilla
to give it flavor.
Right.
Then, from there,
we're just gonna
keep beating it
till it's bright white.
I've made a lot of things,
but this is a first.
All right, we'll transfer it
to a big plastic pan.
And you got to line it
with a ton of powdered sugar
or it's gonna stick like crazy.
As high
as you can pour them.
That is just pure
liquid gold marshmallow.
Crazy. So, we'll
let this set up.
Yeah.
I'm gonna dust the top.
Just so
it doesn't stick to you.
Four inches
by four inches --
That's kind of what
we're going for.
Gotcha. Gotcha.
Mallows are cut.
We're good to go.
Now we're gonna start
building our sandwich.
Graham-cracker crumbs.
Oh, filling it up.
Chocolate sauce.
Gonna fill all them nooks.
Now we're gonna grab one of our
lovely homemade marshmallows.
Now's the fun part.
You can say brûlée,
but I'm not a chef,
so I'm gonna burn it.
That is crazy.
Top it with
our second waffle.
You are whacked.
Got to have fun with food.
Get weird with it.
I am so impressed
with the creativity, man.
Ryder is going banan--
Yes, I'll
bring one home.
Look at that.
Dude, it is like
a gigantic s'more.
Really crazy.
The toasting of it,
the caramelization of
the marshmallow with the torch,
that was
the game changer.
Graham crackers,
got to have it in there.
You need that flavor.
Don't mess with your batter,
'cause you have
that locked down.
Well done.
You are out of control.
Outstanding.
WOMAN:
You're Killin' Me S'Mores.
It does taste really
like a s'more, right?
Wowee. Phenomenal.
It brings me back
to being a kid.
So, these two don't
need an introduction,
but I'll
just remind you.
Panini Pete, Greg
from Pinky's and Penguin.
Both of you make
really creative food.
Tell me about this.
Homemade marshmallows,
and the dust on
the graham crackers
instead of the chunks --
perfect, man.
I wouldn't change a thing,
except my hands are sticky.
[ Laughs ]
The food is a perfect marriage
with the bottle shop.
We have over 550 beers.
We brew our own beer, too.
You brew your own beer?
Yeah.
Can I buy a beer here
and eat over there?
Yeah, yeah.
It's all the same.
Can I eat over here
and buy a beer there?
McELWEE:
Yeah, whatever you want, man.
FIERI: Well, whatever you do,
you got to save room.
'Cause when we come back,
Jeff's getting down
with the Funky Chicken.
MAN: I guarantee if you get the
chicken-and-waffles sandwich,
you will not get anything else.
FIERI: See you in a minute.
FIERI: "Triple D" is
chilling out at FuD At Salud
in Charlotte, North Carolina,
which, I got to tell you,
isn't your typical setup.
McELWEE:
Firing out four waffles.
FIERI: It's Chef Jeff slinging
his waffle-world menu
in the middle of his buddy
Jason's beer store.
We are limited, you know.
We don't have a hood.
We don't have a grill.
McELWEE: Yeah, it's all
electric equipment.
So, we've got to be
really creative.
FIERI: And that means
putting a crazy twist
on this Southern staple.
WOMAN:
I got a Chicken and Waffles.
It's not your normal
chicken and waffles.
We're not doing
fried chicken,
'cause you don't have a hood
and the fryer
and the whole giddyup.
No, it's chicken salad.
Chicken salad
and waffles.
Sounds weird?
We sold three times
as many of those
as anything else
on the menu.
Seriously?
Yeah.
We're gonna pop
this can of chicken open.
Chicken in a can,
dude?
I don't even know
what's gonna happen.
Well, doves fly out,
first, when we open it.
So, we're gonna
drain the juice,
'cause we want this chicken
salad to be flavorful,
but we don't want it
to be watery and gross.
Plop it in a pan.
We're gonna add our mayo.
A couple of shakes
of black pepper.
And then you're gonna
get in there.
Next step,
candying some walnuts.
The butter's melted.
Okay.
And we're gonna
add our walnuts.
Stir them up till
they're nice and coated.
And then add our sugar.
Combine them together.
You don't want them
to caramelize or get burnt
or anything like that.
Okay, let's go.
Let's make the waffle.
All right.
We're gonna start off
by adding candied walnuts.
Big ol' scoop of bacon.
Maple syrup.
Followed by our lovely
canned-chicken salad.
This little guy.
Then you got to slice it
down the middle.
That's one of
the weirdest things
I've seen on the show --
canned chicken.
Thanks, man.
That's really good.
[ Laughs ] Thanks.
I feel like
I'm gonna have to go
to some kind of
a meeting now
and talk about the fact
that I ate canned chicken.
Every time you're supposed
to take a right, you went left.
I mean, everything
does not really fit,
but it goes together
really well.
I was worried you didn't put
any salt in the chicken salad,
but you're getting it
from the bacon.
The candied nuts --
great texture
that you wouldn't expect.
People have got to flip out
about this.
It's dynamite.
Well done, my friend.
Order up,
Chicken and Waffles.
I love Jeff's
chicken salad.
It's a nice play
between the sweetness
of the candied walnuts
and the bacon.
Everything just goes
together so great.
It's just a really unique spot
in a growing neighborhood.
FuD at Salud
is the place to come.
When we say
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
it's really about funky joints
and creative people
that really love
what they're doing.
And, my friend, you are
the shining example.
You have rocked
the house.
Thanks, man.
♪♪
FIERI:
Coming up, I'm hanging with
Hunter at a Houston joint...
I wanted that one.
Come on, now.
FIERI: ...where it's
a little bit Southern...
I think this is the state bird
in Texas, Hunter.
Yeah, I think so.
FIERI:
...and a little bit sushi roll.
Brother, that's thinking
outside the box, there.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Spring, Texas,
30 minutes north
of downtown Houston, and 15 --
Hey, excuse me.
Excuse me.
I'm here, too.
Okay?
Uh, we're
about 15 minutes
from the Bush
International Airport,
and we're here to check out
a joint where a Navy vet --
well, he's decided
to bring barbecue
from around the world and mix it
with a little sushi.
This is Q-Shi.
Nice job, Dad.
Thanks, Hunter.
AKER:
We got crispy barbecue rolls,
Argentinean steak bowl,
and a smoked-meat fried rice.
Let's go
and rock this out.
I come twice a week.
Easily.
Hawaiian bowl, sir.
It's different than any other
Asian-fusion place I've been to.
Spicy Mary roll up.
If you never tried sushi,
but you like barbecue,
this is definitely
a place to try it.
FIERI: And the guy mashing up
the surf and turf
is chef and owner Raymond Aker,
who started cooking 'cue
with his pops
growing up in Georgia.
My dad sold barbecue to
textile mills when I was a kid.
We used to use cinder block
and chain-link fence
to barbecue
a whole hog.
And there's nothing
wrong with that?
Oh, no, it's great.
Comes out great.
I got chain-link fence
in my car if you want some.
"Have chain-link fence,
will party."
Then, while traveling
the world in the Navy,
Raymond picked up
his love of Asian flavor
and worked it into his menu.
Pick up, kimchi fries!
What are
we making today?
Korean barbecue beef that we use
for our Korean kimchi fries.
Our interpretation
of bulgogi.
Okay. Do you have
any questions, Hunter?
Honestly,
I'm just listening
and enjoying the time
with you guys.
[ Laughs ]
So, what's our cut here?
New York strip loin,
chopped.
We're gonna do the brown sugar.
White sugar in there.
Black pepper.
Little sesame seed.
This is chopped garlic.
It's got
the right smell.
We're gonna come in
with the soy sauce.
Jump on in here with
a little bit of sesame oil.
And then we got
the white onion,
and then we got to do
the green onion.
And Hunter was about to ask
how long is this going to...?
We're gonna put this
in the cooler
and let it marinate
and party together
for about 24 hours.
24-hour party.
Now we're going to go ahead
and make the kimchi.
Chef, what is kimchi?
A fermented,
pickled cabbage.
It's a Korean condiment.
I call this
a quick kimchi.
It's quick-chi.
Quick-chi.
Inspired by kimchi.
This is
our arrested cabbage.
I let it sit in salt
water overnight.
And add our kimchi base.
Sambal,
fresh chopped garlic,
and then we do
a Korean chili powder.
And then a little sugar.
We'll put it
in the cooler,
and we'll let it sit
for another day.
Okay, I like it.
Now we're gonna cook off
my bulgogi and my kimchi.
Is this the normal portion
or is this just
a lumberjack portion
'cause Hunter and I are here?
I've seen you eat,
and I got to make sure I --
Don't start.
Put a little bit
of cheese here.
Next comes the bulgogi.
We're gonna hit it
with some kimchi.
Distribute it.
Hit it with spicy mayo,
little sriracha,
then we finish it off --
nice little pop of green onion.
Make it nice and sexy.
I wanted that one.
Come on, now.
That is really good.
That's very good.
The bulgogi's great,
right off the bat.
The sauce almost candies
on the outside of it.
The kimchi -- nice, vinegary.
So, you get the sweet
of the beef,
the sourness
of the kimchi,
the crunch of
the French fries...
That sriracha, too.
...and then the extra kick
from the sriracha, exactly.
Brother, that's thinking
outside the box, there.
Thanks, Guy.
AKER: Kimchi fries up!
I'm gonna cheese 'em
and please 'em and get 'em out.
The bulgogi here is legit.
It's done right.
AKER:
Ribs and brisket rolls, please.
How did you
find this place?
Actually, I was just driving
through the lot one day,
discovered it, and I've been
coming here ever since.
FIERI: And it's tucked
inside a building
built for a pizza chain
in the '70s.
This is vintage.
Vintage.
The show is "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives." You...
Yeah, we dived.
Hey, ballin'
on a budget, baby.
Hey. Ballin'
on a budget.
Have chain-link,
will party.
WOMAN: I've known Ray
for quite a while,
and everything that comes
out of his chef mind
turns out to be
a really great meal.
MAN:
Surf-and-turf roll.
The surf and turf is what
Q-Shi is all about --
a portion of barbecue mixed
with a little bit of sushi.
It's delicious.
AKER: We're gonna do
our surf-and-turf roll, Chef.
Nice big ol' brisket.
I think this is the state bird
in Texas, Hunter.
I think so.
I think you're right.
I season mine
really simply,
with salt, black pepper,
garlic powder.
And how long are we
gonna leave that on?
We're gonna stick this in
the cooler for about 24 hours,
and we'll smoke this
for about 16 hours.
210 degrees.
All right, here we go.
For the surf-and-turf roll,
we like a nice wide slice.
Oh, that one --
Oh, yeah.
All right.
Nice little smoke ring
to it.
Good bark. Good.
All right, we're gonna
make our Japanese dressing
for the surf and turf.
We have sugar and wasabi.
Jalapeño.
Some cilantro.
Put a little bit
of salt in there.
Some horseradish.
Soy sauce.
Sweet chili sauce.
Sriracha?
Sriracha.
Lime juice.
Some water. Mirin.
And the last thing
we're gonna do is
just put a little bit
of sesame oil in here.
Ohh.
See, that's that
Georgia thing.
"Ohh."
Ohh.
That's got all
my favorite flavors.
Mmm!
Wasabi all day.
Now we're gonna
make this roll?
Sushi chef's
doing the roll.
All right, Chef,
take it away.
Rice.
Press it evenly.
Then I'm gonna
go snow crab.
Shrimp tempura.
You put pieces of avocado.
Got it.
And roll it up.
The brisket slice.
This should be interesting.
And I'm gonna put
some jalapeños.
And Japanese dressing.
That's the one
we just made.
And sriracha on top.
They are ready to go.
And that's
all she wrote.
♪♪
In sushi, everything's
got to be in balance.
So, as soon as you take
something like smoky beef,
you got to make sure it doesn't
take the lead in the show.
The sauce that we put
over the top
really kind of balances
that out.
That's really good.
If you're gonna put barbecue
and sushi together,
it better taste
like that.
The tempura shrimp,
it's very crunchy, it's light.
It's also hot and spicy,
which I love.
Well, I think this is
one of the best barbecue places
in the city.
If you're a flavor addict,
this is your fix.
You're treating your barbecue
with respect,
and then you're giving it
another place to play.
Good job.
You'd have loved that, man.
FIERI: Up next, we're headed
south of the border...
Is there somewhere
I can lay down in the sand
and pass out
for about three hours?
...to a place reeling
in recipes
we're not seeing
in the States.
You want
to have something
that really represents an area
like Cancun, that's it.
Get over here right now.
You and your big old melon.
Let's go.
[ Laughs ]
"Big old melon."
Do you have kids?
Uh, I don't.
You want one?
Well, we need workers
around here, Guy.
I'll take Hunter
off your hands.
♪♪
FIERI: Imagine you're
in Cancun, Mexico.
Ahh. You know,
staying at one of those
really big resorts,
all-inclusive.
Well, after three days
in captivity,
you're gonna want to escape
and find some food
where the locals go.
So, I'm here on Boulevard
Kukulcan to check out a joint
that looks like just
a little taco shop upstairs,
but underneath,
oh, it's a whole nother world.
This is El Fish Fritanga.
MAN:
The whole fried fish.
It's a little
hidden gem down here.
Pescado Caribeño.
The fish is great. They catch it
early in the morning.
FIERI: And then owner David
Aguilar serves it up fresh,
both upstairs
in his grab-and-go taco shack
and downstairs
in the full-on restaurant.
It's awesome. I mean, it is
a funky, little, cool hideout.
And calling the shots
in the back is Chef Florentino,
who's been creating
regional recipes
since he was a teen.
Where are you from?
Cancun?
Yucatán.
The Yucatán.
Yeah.
MAN: Most people, when they come
down here on a vacation,
want to eat like the locals,
and this is it.
AGUILAR: Pescadillas up.
The pescadillas are
like empanadas
with shark and tomato sauce.
And this is one of
the specialities of the house?
Yes, it is.
What kind of shark?
[ Speaks
foreign language ]
[Speaks foreign language]
means nurse shark.
That's the nurse shark?
Yeah. There's a lot,
a lot of meat in this.
So, we break it down, then what
are we gonna do with it?
We're gonna boil it.
With just water?
Just water.
What happens when
it's all the way cooked?
You have to take the skin off,
take the bones off,
and you just shred it.
Mmm.
[ Chuckles ]
Now we're gonna
make our tomato sauce.
All right, Chef,
so, we're gonna start off
with the tomatoes
and the onions.
We'll let this cook
for 20 minutes.
Okay. Next?
We're gonna add some meat.
A little bit of garlic.
Some chicken base.
Salt and pepper.
Bay leaves? What do you
call them in Spanish?
Laurel.
Thyme. What do you call it
in Spanish?
Tomillo.
And epazote.
Okay, and how do you say
that in Spanish?
Epazote.
Oh, epazote.
Now, how long
is this gonna cook?
Gonna cook for like 20 minutes.
Then we'll let it cool.
Now we're gonna
form our pescadillas.
So, we have a tortilla,
then we're gonna seal it shut?
Yeah, with toothpicks.
He's gonna put them
in the fryer?
Yes.
Chef, let's do it, buddy.
Now we will remove
the toothpicks,
and it's ready to eat.
So, we got
a pico de gallo.
What is this?
Just red sauce.
And then this one?
It's habaneros.
This looks like the devil.
Yes, it is.
And it's hot?
It is very hot.
Good. I'll stay away
from that one.
So, crunchy
like a taquito.
There you go. Pico de gallo --
little bit of that.
And just some drops
of the hot sauce.
Come on.
One. That's it.
The habanero is hot,
so be careful with it.
There's a lot of
true seafood flavor to it.
Right.
There's not a bunch
of breading around it.
It's great.
What's interesting --
if you used regular fish,
I don't think there would be
any flavor left.
By the time you boiled it,
cooked it, fried it,
it would just kind of
dissolve to nothing.
Yes.
Having the nice little trio
of the salsas is perfect.
To find something
like this handmade,
scratch-made,
you can't beat it, man.
It's your own
little specialty.
Thank you, sir.
Gracias, Jefe.
[ Both chuckle ]
♪♪
Here's our
famous pescadillas.
It is crispy,
it has a tang.
The habanero sauce is awesome.
It's spicy.
You're gonna need something cold
to drink with it.
But it's really good.
AGUILAR:
Ceviche para mesa treinta.
The food is so pretty, I just
want to take a picture of it.
FIERI: And the location is
something out of a postcard.
MAN: It's got great
atmosphere --
the water, the sand
under your feet.
You just feel like you're
in your own private oasis.
Are the boats yours?
No, they're not.
Can we go take a boat?
Yeah, we can.
Fantastic.
FIERI: And being surfside
means using fresh catch
in local dishes like this.
Table four, Tikin-Chik up.
It's an old Mayan recipe.
It's very good.
It's fish with peppers
and onions and tomatoes
in a tomato sauce,
and it's all grilled.
What's next?
AGUILAR:
Pescado tikin-chik.
Tikin-chik?
Yeah.
What kind
of fish is this?
Hogfish.
Hog? [ Snorts ]
Yeah.
What does it
taste like, pork?
[ Chuckling ]
No, not really.
You know you
wanted me to ask that.
It is a
very Caribbean fish.
So, first we're gonna
make the paste to rub the fish?
Yes.
Okay.
The first ingredient
is the achiote base.
We're gonna add
some sour orange.
A little bit of vinegar.
Sweet orange juice.
Orange juice, okay.
Salt and pepper.
Got it.
We're gonna rub a little bit
of butter on the rack.
Couple extra little
texture cuts in there
so it seeps down
inside.
We're gonna add
some salt and pepper.
Some garlic
and some lemon juice.
There is nothing
I don't love about this.
We're gonna brush on
our achiote sauce that we made.
Beautiful.
And then we're gonna add
some sliced tomatoes,
onions, and peppers.
Look at that.
And that's it. Now we're gonna
fire up the grill
and throw it
right on the stove.
Yes.
So, how long?
For 15 minutes.
♪♪
Oh.
You could have cooked this
over a book of matches.
That is dynamite.
Good amount of garlic,
nice flavor of the onions
and the tomato.
That, to me, is the best way
to have the fish.
Yeah.
Fantastic.
That's exactly
what I wanted.
I think of coming down here,
you want to have something
that really represents
an area like Cancun, that's it.
Tikin-chik fish.
The fish is perfectly cooked.
It's not dry.
It's got the right amount
of charred-ness
where it's grilled.
Hoja Santa.
Fish Fritanga is my favorite
restaurant in Cancun.
Chef, gracias.
Gracias, Chef. Very nice.
Is there somewhere
I can lay down in the sand
and pass out
for about three hours?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
I'll be over there.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
from some of the joints
we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
So, Hunter and I went
fishing the other day.
How big was
that fish we caught?
Ryder pulled out one
this big.
Hunter pulled out one...
that big.
[ Laughter ]
HUNTER: Leave your hands there.
Don't move.