Hey, I'm Guy Fieri.
And you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
This trip...
Holy moly.
...break out
your passport...
That's how you
do it right there.
...for a one-way ticket
to Flavortown International.
Give me some of that.
That is gangster, man.
I'm not kidding you.
We're cruising to Cancun...
That's real deal.
...to a tiny spot
putting out grande burritos.
I'm going to need
a raincoat to eat this.
Plus, in Houston...
[ Lebanese accent ]
Taste.
Yes, I taste.
...lights-out-legit
Lebanese...
I do it
the old-fashioned way.
The old-fashioned way.
...and one jamming
Jamaican joint.
It's so good.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here on the southwest
side of Houston, Texas,
in the Galleria area,
and, well, ladies and gentlemen,
that's about
the only part of this
that's going to make any sense.
You see, from what I'm told,
I'm about ready to embark
on a culinary cultural adventure
like I've never seen before.
This is Café Lili.
♪♪
Lebanese salad.
Whoever wants to eat
authentic Lebanese cooking
has to come to Lili's.
-Have a baba ganoush.
I get cravings for this place
when I'm out of town.
Falafel plate
and two kibbie.
Everything here has been
made from scratch.
FIERI: Thanks to owner
Lili Bejjani,
a no-nonsense,
hookah-smoking Lebanese native
who came to the States
in 1970,
cooked at a Houston
hospital for 20 years
and eventually opened this place
in 1991.
From all my heart, like,
our guest is like my family.
Lili is like Houston's grandma
essentially.
WOMAN: It definitely seems like
she sat me down at her table
and made me all of this herself.
-Here's your fried kibbie.
Lili is famous
for her kibbie balls.
They're fried on the outside,
and then, on the inside,
it has the flavorful
ground beef.
It's my favorite.
What are we making?
We're making
the kibbie filling.
We start with the raw meat.
She's jumping
right into things.
Once we brown the meat,
then we brown the onion.
Now you're in the know.
Browning the meat,
then we'll be
browning the onions.
Right.
Where did you
get this recipe from?
My mother.
Where did your mother
get it from?
From her mother.
Is there
a Lebanese Betty Crocker?
No.
[ Both laugh ]
You're funny.
[ Laughter ]
Okay.
Salt and pepper.
Now we put the cinnamon.
Allspice.
And then this is your secret
ingredient, the cloves?
Yes. Yes.
Mixed together.
Got it.
Try it. Be careful.
Don't burn your hand.
I like it in my hand.
It's mixed well,
has the spices and everything?
Very nice spice.
Does everybody,
when they come here
and they say,
"I want to have a kibbie,"
and then they come,
and then you just,
"One kibbie,"
in the hand?
No. [ Laughs ]
No!
[ Laughter ]
Okay.
So what do we have here?
The raw meat
for kibbie shell.
The kibbie shell.
Yeah.
Of course we are,
dummies.
We're going to make it
creamy.
So now we start this?
Yes.
We put some ice in it
to make it
elastic-looking.
Think of this as
a gigantic buffalo chopper
like you're going
to make hot-dog meat,
and you're going to really cream
it all the way through.
Right.
Now we're making the shell.
This is the bulgur wheat.
Oh, the bulgur wheat.
Right.
When I was a kid,
I used to eat a lot of bulgur.
Really?
Yeah, my parents
were hippies.
Let's put now cinnamon.
Okay.
Allspice.
Salt and pepper.
Salt and pepper,
got it.
Creamy onion.
Little bit of water.
The shell is shaped
like a football,
the American football,
and my children, all of them,
play football.
I saw them.
They're huge.
My husband,
professional wrestler.
Yes.
We travel all over,
but then here we like it
in United States.
You want me
to grab the meat?
Yes, please.
There's the creamy meat.
Now I want to mix it.
So, the meat's going to work
as a binder with the bulgur...
Right.
...and the spices,
and that's going
to make the shell
that we're going to put
the kibbie with the onions,
the filling, inside of.
Right. Okay.
This is the filling.
This is has the spices
and the onion and everything.
Cool.
So toasted pine nuts.
Mix it. Taste.
Oh, whoa.
Taste.
Yes, I taste.
Delicious.
[ Chuckles ]
Now we stuff it.
It's a lot of work.
It is.
Look at that.
So now we're going
to fry these?
Yes.
350 degrees?
Yes, sir.
A football.
Open it.
Okay.
Delicious.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
Look inside of here.
The bulgur with the meat
on the outside
is so moist.
You want to talk about
super flavorful
and not heavy.
The meat and the bulgur
making the crust, genius.
Outstanding.
No more.
No, try the baba ganoush.
I got to...
You know
what the French call that?
Lebanese caviar.
This is fresh eggplant.
We smoke it.
Mm-hmm.
We peel it.
We grind it.
We put the honey sauce,
lemon juice, salt.
The honey sauce. A good smoke
on the baba ganoush.
Right. I do it
the old-fashioned way.
The old-fashioned way.
Right.
That's right. OG.
Original gangster.
[ Both laugh ]
I love the kibbie balls,
so good.
I don't think I've
ever had anything with
such unique flavor.
She use the best ingredients
in terms of meat.
WOMAN: Always great to come
to Café Lili's
and have it just like
my grandma cooked it.
-It's very special here.
-Here's the deal.
I'm hanging out here
at Café Lili in Houston, Texas.
If you don't see me
come back next week
because I'm still here
trying the rest of the menu
like this
Middle-Eastern classic.
Chicken kebab and hummus.
The chicken is very tender,
very juicy.
The best hummus in Houston.
See you in a bit.
Oh, grape leaves.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're at Café Lili
here in Houston, Texas.
Actually, it should be
called Lili, Texas,
because
when you come here,
if you don't find yourself
in Café Lili,
you're missing out.
The freshest plate
of Lebanese food I've had.
As authentic as it gets.
It's like Mama's cooking.
We made
the fried kibbie ball.
Over commercial,
she brought me more food...
so I've had
about 17 lunches, thank you.
And we're gonna have
one more dish.
-Chicken kebabs.
-The chicken kebabs
are super tender and juicy.
The garlic sauce is just
a great complement.
What is this dish?
This, the chicken kebab,
chicken breast,
boneless, skinless.
Okay.
We cut it up,
and we're going to marinate it.
What are we
marinating it in?
Salt, pepper,
granulated garlic,
and we'll mix it together,
lemon juice
and vegetable oil.
Hey, you keep doing that.
I'll be right back.
Now, this is...
What...
...embarrassing.
...is going on here?
That's me...
Huh?
...in 1973.
Holy moly.
Beautiful.
Thank you.
I stole that
in the lobby.
I'm putting it in my car.
Okay?
That's okay.
I'm just going to cut
this guy out right here.
Yeah, tell him.
Tell him?
Tell him. Her husband's
sitting out there.
[ Laughs ]
Okay. How long do
we let that marinate?
For two hours.
Two hours. Okay.
And then we're going
to put that on a kebab
and go on the grill.
Grill it.
So we've got vermicelli rice,
the hummus.
Hummus, the pita bread.
The garlic sauce.
What's in
the garlic sauce?
Whole-bean garlic,
little bit salt, lemon juice
and vegetable oil.
All right. The chicken's ready.
That's for me, huh?
Yes.
What is the right way
to eat it?
Okay?
Okay.
Garlic sauce.
Mm. Chicken's so tender.
Another bite?
Yes.
Not usually when I do
the show does anybody
make all the bites
and give them to me to eat.
Usually, I make the bite.
I eat, and I say,
"Ah, it's really good."
[ Laughs ]
Mm.
There's only a few
ingredients in hummus,
a couple ingredients
in the garlic sauce,
couple ingredients
in the chicken.
Everything is so simple,
but it's the balance
between how much,
the quality of
the ingredients, the method.
If you do all of
those things correct,
that's the simplicity
of the Lebanese food,
but that's also what
makes it so delicious.
That's right.
It's fantastic.
Chicken kebab.
I love the chicken.
It's very tasty.
Cooked to perfection.
-The hummus is velvety smooth.
-The best in town.
If you want to get
a healthy comfort meal,
just come to Lili's.
It's like coming
to eat in Lebanon.
I know why people love you,
because the food is fantastic.
It's wholesome,
very flavorful, scratch-made,
and it's from the heart.
This has been an experience.
Thank you.
Get ready, America.
This is Café Lili.
She's out of control.
Thank you.
Adios.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
we're sticking to Houston...
Fantastic.
...but grabbing
Jamaican...
Oh, get down deep
where it's nice and hot.
There you go.
...for some outrageous oxtail
and gangster goat.
You "goat" to do it.
Just "goat" for it.
I watch you on TV,
and you eat big bite.
And you do like this.
I thought you're going
to be fat, but you're not.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
I got to tell you,
there's certain foods
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives,"
and when I hear about it and I
hear they're doing it great,
well, I got to stop
and check it out,
and one of those is Jamaican.
So I'm here on the southwest
side of Houston, Texas,
to check out a funky joint
where I hear this couple
is crushing it.
This is Cool Runnings.
♪♪
Jerk chicken.
You can tell the love
when you walk into this place.
Here's your curry chicken.
Sometimes, I come for lunch,
and then I'm here again
for dinner.
Steamed fish.
Stepping into the door
makes you feel like
you're stepping
into the island.
FIERI: That's 'cause
Terron Henry is from the island
and has been cooking up
Jamaican favorites
since he was a kid.
When I got here
to Houston,
I wasn't pleased with
the Jamaican product,
so I thought I could get
in there and do a better job.
So he and his wife, Janay,
started out catering
but have been rocking this joint
since 2009.
Seven days a week?
Eight days a week.
Every time I come in, I never
see Terron standing still.
He's always running around.
-Oxtail, table number nine.
You can't have a Jamaican
restaurant without oxtail.
The oxtail is full of flavor,
really nice to eat.
It's the best.
Okay.
So we're going
to make the oxtail.
Yeah.
Let's do it.
Start everything
with a jerk rub --
onion, thyme,
allspice, ginger, garlic.
And where'd you learn
this recipe?
Grandparents.
It's a family recipe.
Brown sugar,
salt and pepper,
a little cayenne pepper,
cinnamon,
of course
habanero pepper, water.
Getting the smoke
coming off the horizon.
Blend it
for about a minute.
That's my house jerk.
Little heat in there.
Okay. So we're
into the oxtails.
Then let it sit
in the refrigerator overnight.
Beautiful. Okay, Chef,
so we're marinated?
Yes. Start off with
some vegetable oil.
The oxtail?
Just add a little water
so it doesn't get too dry.
I have my browning.
Your what?
My browning, which is
like a burned sugar, molasses.
Okay.
Some soy sauce,
garlic.
A bunch of garlic.
Let this go
for about an hour,
continue turning it.
And let it go in the oven
for another hour?
Yeah.
Okay, boss.
Now we're going
to make my sauce.
The sauce for the oxtail?
For Jamaican oxtail,
you've got to have
your lima beans.
Okay. And that's the pot
that we cook the oxtail in?
That's the pot
I put the oxtail in.
Okay.
Some carrots, some onion,
little more garlic, thyme,
brown sugar,
and, of course, save
the braising from the oxtail.
The fat
that rendered down.
I'm going to have this cook
for about 15 minutes,
and we're going to drop
our spinners in.
Our what?
Spinners.
It's flour, salt, water.
So it's your roux?
It's more of a dumpling
than a roux.
Going to pick it off,
spoon them off.
Spinners.
So if you ever go
in a spot
and they don't got spinners
in their oxtail,
it's not Jamaican oxtail.
It's not real deal?
No.
Next up?
Some tomato sauce,
put my oxtails in.
Now I'm gonna add
my bell pepper,
thyme, green onion,
a little bit more
of a wet jerk.
Another 15 minutes,
they'll be done, ready to serve.
All right.
Let's get this going.
Going to start off
with my rice and peas.
Next up is the oxtails,
callaloo.
What's in callaloo?
Callaloo is pretty much
just another green vegetable.
We just put a little bit
of bell pepper,
a little bit of salt
and pepper in it
and plantains.
Oh, dude.
♪♪
FIERI: There's so much flavor,
not just in the fact
that the oxtail is braised
in the jerk season,
but the oxtail itself.
Super tender.
I mean, this is going to be
like the best
Sunday pot-roast gravy
that your grandma made.
The callaloo
is dynamite.
There's no overpowering
flavors here.
Everybody works together
really well.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
-Fantastic.
-Enjoy your oxtails.
They have the best oxtails
here.
-It's delicious.
-Jerk seasoning,
it really adds a lot of heat
and pepper to it.
First dish I cook for her
was some oxtails.
I never had them before.
It was the oxtail.
You never had oxtail?
I never had them.
Where are you from?
I'm from
Oakland, California.
Where'd you guys meet?
Down here?
In Ocho Rios, Jamaica.
The stars were aligned
and then to open up
a restaurant?
Yep. [ Laughs ]
Got it.
-Curry chicken.
-Coming up. Coming up.
-Good job, Ango.
-Terron is a great man,
and his food
is off the chain.
TERRON: Goat, white rice.
Curry goat is really
my favorite.
Flavors are really bold.
It's really awesome.
Love me some goat,
nice and lean.
TERRON: We're going to add
our house wet jerk.
Some Madras curry powder.
Vegetable oil.
Okay.
Let this marinate
for 24 hours
and then we'll cook it
on the stove.
Yeah. Put a little more
vegetable oil in my pot.
Now I want to burn
the Madras curry
a little bit to get
more flavors out of it.
Okay.
Bit more garlic.
Get my goat in.
Gorgeous.
You "goat" to do it.
Just "goat" for it.
You "goat" to take chances.
[ Chuckles ]
Little bit of water.
Add any more water
and you'll make goat tea.
[ Laughter ]
Next up, carrot,
onions, some thyme.
We're going to have this cook
for about an hour
and let it get
nice and tender.
We're going to add in
some potatoes.
All right, Chef.
It's goat time.
TERRON: Gonna first
put some white rice in.
Now we're going
to put our goat on it.
Oh, get down deep
where it's nice and hot.
There you go.
The cabbage.
Put some plantains.
I like this.
♪♪
FIERI: That's how you
do it right there.
That is some of
the most tender,
flavorful, balanced,
curried goat I've ever had,
not super game-y.
Anybody that tells me
they don't like goat
has not been
to Cool Runnings.
Mm. Nice little bit of spice
coming from the jerk.
The rice
is a perfect foil.
The toasting of the spice
in the oil was really nice.
That gravy flows through
the rivers of Flavortown.
If this had a motor in it,
this would be
a goat-er boat.
[ Laughter ]
Look at that. Ugh.
Give me some of that, man.
Thanks for that, man.
Give me some of that.
That is gangster, man.
Thanks.
Killer.
-Enjoy your curry goat.
-Thank you.
The curry goat reminds me
of my grandmother's
cooking in Jamaica.
It's very similar to beef,
but it's more flavorful.
It definitely feels
like Jamaica in Houston.
Cool Runnings,
"Just goat for it."
I want
one of those t-shirts.
You the man.
Up next, we're headed
down to Cancun...
[ Whistles ]
...for a fully loaded
favorite...
I mean,
that's a lot of burrito.
...and a story
that might surprise you.
None of it makes sense.
The rum punch?
That's correct.
What's in
good rum punch?
Rum.
[ Laughter ]
I'm gonna
go out on a limb
and say I think he's right.
That's probably true.
♪♪
So, if you've ever been
to Cancun, Mexico,
you know this walk,
club area down there
headed back to the hotels.
And on this trek,
you'll find everything you need.
You got markets. You got joints
for surplus and excursions.
My question is,
why no burrito shops?
Well, until you get here --
This is Surfin Burrito.
Veggie burrito!
The burritos
are pretty much
the best burritos
I've ever had.
Jamaican jerk tacos!
How did you find
Surfin Burrito?
Walk right by it
all the time.
If you blink,
you will be by it.
Yes.
But it is legit, right?
No, it's great, man.
-Hey. Jerk chicken.
-All right.
It's excellent and amazing
for the tourists
and the locals equally.
FIERI: Because it's put together
by a former tourist
who became a local
when he said adios
to his photography business
in Toronto.
And with about $5,000,
Cory McKay cashed
in on a Cancun secret.
No burrito joints?
Zero burrito joints.
I brought the burrito
to Cancun.
Mahi shrimp burrito!
The shrimp and mahi-mahi is
definitely one of my favorites.
MAN:
We have corn, beans, rice,
onion and green pepper,
and it's amazing.
Why that burrito
versus just, like,
a picadillo
or a carne asada?
Mahi-mahi
is a regional fish.
It's my personal favorite
white fish of the sea.
Okay.
Cut off a portion.
All right.
So we cube up the mahi.
What's next?
Very simple marinade.
So we have
the guajillo peppers,
which is
my favorite pepper,
a little hot water,
puree that up.
That's it.
Now we let it marinate
overnight so it's ready to cook.
So this is for one of
the salsas you guys make?
This is a salsa roja.
All right.
Fire it up, man.
We've got roasted onions,
roasted tomatoes
and roasted garlic.
Cilantro?
Yeah, and salt.
And that's it
for the salsa roja?
Yeah.
Mm. I'll take that
on a burrito any day.
All right. So now
marinated mahi, the shrimp.
You get the shrimp fresh?
Yeah.
All that goes
in one burrito?
That's it.
[ Whistles ]
Now we're going
to add the veggies.
Tomatoes, green bell peppers,
onions and corn?
And corn.
Hey. We're in Mexico.
People love corn here.
You buy the tortillas
fresh local.
Yep.
Okay.
We're gonna
melt some cheese.
Throw the beans on.
These are dry beans.
Dry beans.
Okay.
Tomato rice.
♪♪
That's
a ridiculous burrito.
Now we're going to
add all the goods.
First, we're going to
add pico de gallo, lettuce.
Now we're going
to add our sauces --
first, tamarind sauce.
All of those sauces
are going on?
Those are
all going on here.
Sour cream, chipotle.
I'm gonna need a raincoat.
Jesus.
Our habanero sauce.
Think you.
Really loaded that up.
You're going to
feel this one.
Avocado sauce.
This is the salsa roja
that we just made.
Okay.
♪♪
So, back on the grill.
Do we sear
a few sides of it?
That's absolutely the key.
Everything gets to mix together.
And it'll be ready to go
in about 2 minutes.
♪♪
And that's how
it's handed off.
This thing's got to weigh
a pound and a half.
Yeah, it is about that.
Really good tortilla.
Love the corn.
And you don't skimp, man.
You give
a lot of seafood,
rice and beans
made from scratch.
Love it.
I just got the habanero.
There we go.
The habanero's hot.
Good.
You sure deliver
on a burrito, man.
I mean,
that's real deal.
Hey, guys. Here you go.
The shrimp is
just really tender.
It's not overcooked.
Right amount of spices
build perfectly.
It's just
a really good burrito.
Mango shrimp ceviche!
After a big, long day
of sun and surf,
we love to come back here
and dive
into that fresh seafood.
FIERI: And people are diving in
all night long.
We never close.
24/7?
This place has maybe two or
three slow hours in the morning,
and that's it.
This place is busy.
It's a great spot
to just grab a bite
while you're going
to the beach.
Fajita nachos!
An amazing little hole
in the wall
that serves awesome food.
None of it makes sense --
photographer, Toronto,
less than 5,000 bucks,
serving up big burritos.
But this nonsense equation
turns out
a hell of a burrito, dude.
I mean,
that's a lot of burrito.
I will be back, brother.
You're a man of the people.
That's it.
I'm giving back.
♪♪
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
I don't usually interview people
with better hair than me,
but I got three people
so let's just not focus on
how awesome their hair is.
[ Laughter ]