Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
...we're unhinging the jaw...
You don't do much small,
do you?
...for some major mouthful.
Will there be nine lumberjacks
who will come to eat this?
I'm not kidding you,
just listen to the lineup.
That's the official
football of Flavortown.
We got the boss
and the sauce in Jersey...
I've never seen
anybody go this far.
...the hulk in Louisville...
That's a bite
right there.
...and in Oregon,
the whole shabamwich.
I don't know exactly
how to attack this.
It's a loosen‐the‐belt...
That is ridiculous.
...and strap‐on‐a‐napkin
kind of show.
I'm having a difficult time
trying to host my show
as I'm shoveling this as fast
as I can into my face.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
You know I love being
from California.
We got some of
the best of the best,
but what I wish we had more of
is old‐school Italian Delis
like this, where they're
scratch‐making
their own desserts.
They got a deli case
full of everything.
We're talking about
prepared meals.
We're talking fresh pasta,
homemade sausage.
I mean, you name it,
they got it.
So, the next time
you find yourself
in Robbinsville, New Jersey,
you got to check out
Dolce &amp; Clemente's.
‐Yay!
‐Right on.
Stuffed roast pork is ready.
Come get it.
‐Just an awesome place.
‐Who's next?
Authentic Italian,
there's nothing here that isn't.
So you got the ricotta
after the sauce?
MAN: More than 100 fresh,
home‐cooked items
every single day.
Locatelli.
FIERI: Which are Italian
specialties owner Joe Clemente
has learned over a lifetime.
I started when I was 9
in my family's business.
That was Clemente's
Italian market in Brooklyn,
not far from the butcher shop
that Joe's father‐in‐law,
Frank Dolce, grew up in.
‐Dolce Meats.
I started 8 years old.
FIERI: And after Joe spent time
as a New York City cop,
he and Frank joined forces
to open up this mother
of a market deli and restaurant.
And what did the family
think of this idea?
‐It was terrible.
‐Nobody was excited?
‐No.
‐But it's a perfect combo.
‐Yeah.
You got everything
from sauces to salads.
And homemade Italian bread
that is just delicious.
I'll take one
prosciutto bread, please.
MAN:
That prosciutto bread,
my most favorite thing
that Dolce &amp; Clemente serves.
Filled with all different
varieties of meat.
‐Stuffed prosciutto bread?
‐Mm‐hmm.
Hit it.
First I'm going
to put in the prosciutto.
It's so quiet.
Next, we'll put
the ham in, mortadella.
Ground‐up mortadella.
That should've been
my middle name.
Next, I'm going
to put the soppressata in.
Where'd this recipe
come from?
My grandfather.
Pepperoni.
During the holidays,
we'll sell between
15,000 to 20,000
of these Christmas week.
‐I'm sorry, 15 what?
‐20,000.
‐Of this?
‐Of these.
‐And you bake them all here.
‐All here.
I put the provolone
last so it can grab
all the meat
that's left inside there.
I dig it.
Then we put
the crushed black pepper.
I would like a snow cone
of that please.
Just for science.
It's so good.
Don't touch that.
We're going
to make the dough now.
So, we'll dump the water
in the mixer bowl, yeast.
Salt and sugar together.
Next is the oil.
Type of flour
we're working with?
High gluten.
‐Like a pizza dough flour.
‐Like a pizza dough flour, yep.
‐On the mixer, how long?
‐About 10‐12 minutes.
Then we portion it,
then we let them rest overnight.
Okay.
This is how we've been
doing it for years in my family.
Push it down on one side
and flip it over.
You make sure you got enough
on the other side.
And you pick it up
and fold over.
Fold it over
from the outside.
Start making your fold.
And you just roll it.
That's the official
football of Flavortown.
I got to see that again.
Set some music to it.
Maybe Italian opera.
[ Opera music plays ]
Then we bake it off.
What temp?
350, 38 minutes.
‐Not 37?
‐38 exactly.
[ Whistles ]
Too pretty to cut.
No, you got to cut one
to try.
‐All right.
Stromboli gone wild.
You take some olive oil,
extra virgin, some locatelli.
I'm setting this out
for Christmas.
Just little parsley
to dress it up.
So, here you go.
That's...
Ah, it's too pretty
to eat.
No, it's not.
That is ridiculous.
And when you cook
these Italian meats
and you let all the fat
cook into the dough,
you just get all the flavor.
The depth of flavor
in this is massive.
The key, though,
is how you cook the meat
on the outside
of the bread.
Gives it that crunch.
Out of bounds.
Seriously, out of bounds.
‐Thank you.
‐Oh, you want this for sure.
Trust me.
One more bite
just for you.
An order
of prosciutto bread.
You could eat it for breakfast,
lunch or dinner.
It has a really good kick
to it, too, kind of spicy.
‐Got a little heat to it?
‐Got a little heat.
‐So what can I do for you?
‐Some vodka rigatoni.
Vodka rig, how much
would you like?
WOMAN: Anything that you could
possibly think of to make
for a Sunday family dinner
is available in Dolce
&amp; Clemente's.
If you lived in a 5‐mile radius
of this place,
you'd rip your kitchen
out of your house.
‐That's right.
‐And make an extra bedroom.
Because you don't need
a kitchen.
Boss of the sauce up.
Boss of the sauce, you could
feed an army with it.
Pork and beef braciole,
baby back ribs,
homemade meatballs.
‐All in the sauce?
‐All in the sauce.
Boss of the sauce.
‐You're going to love this.
See you in a bit.
FIERI: Welcome back.
"Triple D" is hanging out
at Dolce &amp; Clemente's
in Robbinsville,
New Jersey,
where this
ex‐police officer
has come together
with his father‐in‐law
to make,
I'm not kidding you,
one of the most
outrageous delis
you've ever seen
in your life.
What else
would you like today?
They simply offer
everything Italian.
Boss of the sauce.
MAN:
Boss of the sauce reminds me
of my grandmother's
Sunday dinner.
WOMAN:
Meatballs, sausage, braciole.
Everybody in the house
winds up happy from one dish.
Now,
who started this dish?
Really, my grandmother.
She called it Sunday sauce.
Sunday sauce.
So, let's start
with beef braciole.
‐Do you sleep?
‐Not much.
For the braciole,
I use top round of beef.
And we're going to pound
it a little.
Now we're going
to pound these out.
Salt and pepper,
house‐made bread crumb,
chopped parsley.
Parsley. Oh!
Little garlic.
Your family have interest
in a breath‐mint company?
Next is the soppressata.
And then we go provolone.
We roll them up.
Take some butcher's string
and you're done.
‐Okay, meatballs now.
‐Chopped beef, pork and veal.
We're going to
pour the eggs.
‐Parmesan?
‐Sicilian oregano.
‐I could smell it from here.
‐Stems and all.
Tomato paste,
chopped parsley,
house‐made bread crumb,
chopped garlic,
salt and pepper.
Knead them by hand.
You don't do much small,
do you?
No.
‐Bake them off?
‐About 42 minutes, 325 degrees.
I don't know if
I should bow to it.
This is the almighty.
This is ridiculous.
Fire me up, boss.
All right, so oil and real,
natural butter, chopped celery.
So you got
your mirepoix going.
Carrots, Spanish onion,
sliced garlic.
With the razor blade
like in "Goodfellas"?
‐No, I use a mandolin.
‐Okay.
Then I start to set
in da meats.
‐Da.
‐Da. Da.
And so we're going
to put the pork ribs in it,
next we do a little
pork for gravy.
‐I'm sorry what?
‐Pork for gravy.
‐There you go, beef for gravy.
‐Yeah.
‐Pork braciole's next.
Pork braciole also,
real underachiever.
Beef braciole, hot sausage,
fennel sausage.
‐All made here?
‐All made here.
Can't believe
there's nothing else.
Want to put a shoe in there,
a baseball glove?
San Marzano tomatoes,
crushed by hand.
‐Okay.
‐And tomato paste.
Salt and pepper,
oregano.
After that's cooked
for a while,
we're going to add
the fresh basil.
‐And then the meatballs.
This goes for four hours.
And then we'll serve
this with pasta?
‐Pockety.
‐Pockety?
Pockety,
giant rigatoni.
‐I'm so dumb.
‐You're not dumb.
You're just
from California.
You're not dumb.
You're just from California.
Okay, Boss of the sauce.
That's a wristband.
Just plate it right
on top of the pasta
and put the sauce
right on top,
a big dollop
of fresh ricotta.
I like how you
really do things subtly,
really delicate.
It's such finesse.
Chopped parsley and then
fresh‐grated locatelli.
‐What's locatelli?
‐It's basically Pecorino Romano.
Uh‐huh.
Just on a higher
classification and that's it.
Look at that.
That's, um, ridiculous.
I've never seen
anybody go this far.
The pork braciole,
the beef braciole,
the homemade sausage,
the homemade meatballs,
all those things
put together.
But you really take it
over the top
and that's kind of
the attitude or the energy
that I'm catching
from the whole place.
Yeah.
Because everything
is over the top.
You're cooking for people
like it's your daughter's
wedding day.
I try.
I find them all
and you are truly a gem.
Outstanding.
Here's a beef braciole.
Yeah, it's like
a meat heaven.
A good buddy of mine,
Roland and his friend Noah.
Roland has a fantastic show
on SiriusXM, channel 206
called
"Roland's Food Court."
He does that with my buddy,
Carl Ruiz. What do you think?
This is one of the best sauces
I've ever tasted.
So meaty, rich, delicious.
‐This is so much food.
Take that home.
You got a couple
of days of leftovers.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
MAN: Dolce &amp; Clemente's,
each and every time
will exceed your expectations.
Awesome place,
the whole thing.
‐Thank you. Thank you.
‐Very impressed.
I appreciate it.
FIERI: Coming up
in Louisville, Kentucky...
This is funky.
...over‐the‐top seafood.
It's really good.
...at an under‐the‐radar
kind of joint.
You might be up there
in the championship
dive joints
of "Triple D."
Welcome back.
Triple ‐‐
5, 4, 3, 2. No,
not the hug. [ Laughs ]
So, the name of the show
is "Diners, Drive‐Ins
and Dives."
Oh, we find a good amount
of drive‐ins,
quite a few diners,
but we don't find many dives.
So I'm here in Louisville,
Kentucky, at a joint
that's in an old tire shop.
That sounds like a dive to me.
This is The Seafood Lady.
Cajun crawfish.
This is the definition of good,
Southern seafood cooking.
NICHELLE: Fried gator up.
She brought a taste of Florida
to Kentucky
that we really needed.
‐Where'd you get the recipe?
‐My grandfather.
He was a chef
in the Navy for a while.
He cooked
for so many people.
FIERI:
And when Nichelle Thurston
came up from Florida
to her husband Luke's hometown,
she began cooking
for big crowds, too.
I would come home to like
30‐40 people on my porch,
I'll be like, "Hold up."
‐No.
‐Yeah.
FIERI: So they knew it was time
to make it official
and The Seafood Lady was born.
WOMAN: You can't go anywhere
in Louisville, Kentucky,
and get this type of seafood.
For you, sir,
the full combo.
The full combo plate
is crab legs,
shrimp, potatoes, corn,
boiled egg and sausage.
If you're hungry, that's
definitely the dish to get.
Okay,
what are we making first?
The Cajun boil
and full combo.
Cajun boil
You get bay leaves,
black peppercorns.
‐Oregano.
‐Pickling spice,
cinnamon, mustard seeds.
This is
your grandpa's recipe?
Yes. Paprika,
red pepper flakes.
Whole mess of Cayenne.
Fresh dill, sea salt.
‐Adobo.
‐Coriander.
‐Thyme.
‐Cardamom seeds.
Kitchen sink.
Ginger, whole onion,
green onion and celery.
And then we'll add...
‐Potatoes.
...corn, smoked sausage.
Whole eggs.
That's like the little gem
that everybody gets.
‐I know you hate eggs.
‐Snow crab, shrimp.
We'll cook this
for about 15 minutes
until the potatoes
are done.
Okay.
‐All right.
We're going to make
the full combo platter.
Two potato halves,
one snow crab cluster,
one full ear of corn,
two of your smoked sausage,
10 jumbo shrimps.
‐Shells on?
‐Yes.
One Cajun boiled egg
and then you add
the house sauce on top,
which is butter,
garlic, Cayenne,
Cajun seasoning, lemon juice,
lime juice and onion powder.
And then we add the Cajun
seasoning and parsley.
Perfect.
Just want to make sure
in front of The Seafood Lady
that I got stuff right.
Just warming up.
[ Laughs ]
Shrimp's great. Crab's great.
Tons of flavor.
You know you do
your spices right.
Mmm, I love this
house sauce on top.
‐Kicks it out.
‐Oh, yeah.
That Cajun dust
at the end is spot on.
I'm having
a difficult time
trying to host
my show right now
as I'm shoveling this as fast
as I can into my face.
That's really good.
Back to business.
[ Laughs ]
It's exciting taste.
Kind of a down‐home
Southern flavor.
You know Damaris Phillips.
One of our judges,
one of our competitors
on "Triple D."
So, it's legit, right?
‐It's so good.
And for this Louisville native,
it's super familiar.
She said it's right next
to my parent's old house.
Literally next door.
When we were little kids,
this was a tire shop called,
Don't boot that tire,
cap it.
What it?
Don't boot that tire, Guy.
Cap it.
Ah, I think Seafood Lady
sounds way better.
WOMAN:
It's kind of a hole in the wall,
but it's always
a line out the door.
I mean, this just has
so much personality.
‐It does.
‐This Saturday, I sing here.
The Seafood Lady
has a lounge.
And it's a lot
of great food.
For you, ma'am,
we have the hulk.
The hulk is fried lobster,
fried shrimp
and a buttermilk waffle.
All right,
lobster and waffles,
my life is complete.
‐What are we making now?
We're going to make
a house‐made waffle.
I'm going to put the flour,
baking powder,
sugar, salt,
little oil, two eggs,
vanilla, milk.
I like it a little thick,
so I can get
a really fluffy waffle.
All right.
We're going
to make the fry batter
for the lobster
and the shrimp.
‐Okay.
‐Yellow cornmeal.
And this again
is one of grandpa's?
Yes, all
grandpa's secrets.
Flour, onion powder,
granulated garlic,
Cayenne pepper,
paprika, adobo,
black pepper,
sea salt and thyme.
Got to have the thyme.
Now what happens?
Pop this sucker open,
roll him out.
Like old‐school
dinner‐house style.
And then we'll batter
the shrimp.
Deep fry the whole tail
and the shell.
Now we're going to
pull the waffle out.
Okay.
I'm going to top it
with the deep‐fried lobster,
deep‐fried shrimp,
top off with mayo, parsley.
Then you serve it
with syrup.
There you have it ‐‐
the hulk.
That's a good‐looking
lobster tail.
Thank you.
The dredge...
out of bounds.
It's not heavy,
not too much.
You don't overcook your
seafood, which is great.
You got
that seafood hand.
Get a piece of waffle,
tear off a chunk
of that shrimp
and a little bit
of that sauce.
That's a bite right there.
Order up, hulk.
The fried lobster
is just definition of amazing.
WOMAN: Mixed with
the buttermilk waffle,
I really can't explain it.
But it dances in my mouth
and it works perfect.
NICHELLE:
Lobster and cheesy fry up.
No other place in Louisville
compares to The Seafood Lady.
There's a line of people
outside right now
and I know why because
you're killing it.
This is funky.
You might be up there
in the championship
dive joints of "Triple D."
Yes.
FIERI: Up next, a legit food
truck in Portland, Oregon...
I like the way you roll.
...'cueing it up...
That nice smoke ring
right there.
...and doing it right.
Come on, dude, you can't get
any better than that.
I'm here in Northeast
Portland, Oregon,
in the parking lot
of a pawn shop
and the story just gets weirder.
You see, there's a dude
from Long Island
and he moves all the way
to Australia
to study Texas barbecue.
That's right.
Then he comes back
with his Australian wife.
Well, they travel
across country
to the west coast
and they open up this joint.
This is Matt's BBQ.
Hot mess and
a chopped brisket sandwich.
This is such a step above
any other place in Portland.
It's always like this?
Always packed?
Always like this, yeah.
Can we get four of
the pulled pork tacos?
It's just incredible.
FIERI: All the hype is
for Matt Vicedomini,
who ditched New York City
fine dining to head down under.
VICEDOMINI: And I took a job
as a sous‐chef
and they had a smoker
in the back
and they were making
Texas‐style barbecue
and, yeah,
I just got hooked.
So hooked that he came back
to the States,
tasted the best barbecue
around the country
and finally found
a place to park.
Portland is not south,
but Matt's bringing it
right here in a food cart.
And the favorite thing
that he has on the menu
that you enjoy?
WOMAN: I love the ribs the most.
They're delicious.
We're related if you couldn't
tell from the hair.
VICEDOMINI: Half pound of ribs
with pinto beans.
The way he smokes them
puts just this
incredible bark on it.
All right, big Matt's BBQ,
we got a full spare rib.
‐That's right.
‐Show me the magic.
So, yeah, first thing we're
going to do is trim it down,
round it out.
‐Okay.
We're just going
to season them.
All our rubs are salt
and pepper, Texas style,
and we'll put them on the smoker
for four to six hours.
We run pretty hot,
roughly around 275.
I like to say hot and slow,
not low and slow.
We get a great bark
on our ribs.
I'm expecting at 275,
we better.
All right.
So this is
for our smoked garlic jelly,
which we turn into
our rib glaze.
Onions and garlic?
Yeah, we're going to get
a lot of smoke on there.
‐How long?
‐Two hours maybe.
Add some vinegar
and let it soak overnight.
Soften it up a bit
and then
we're going to go
to an immersion blender.
Yup. We're going
to add our sugar,
cook this for about
20 to 30 minutes.
So, this is just
the jelly not the glaze?
Mmm, I don't know what
you're going to put that on
but anything would be good.
‐Yeah.
So, we're making
the rib glaze now.
Equal parts of ketchup
and jelly.
That's right.
Worcestershire.
Worcestershire sauce?
Just whisk it up.
Ribs just came
off the smoker.
We'll take
our barbecue sauce
on the foil,
put the ribs on,
I'm just going to hit it
with the glaze here.
Flip them, barbecue sauce
in the back
and then they're ready
to get wrapped.
And how long you're
leaving them wrapped?
I like to rest for at least
a half an hour
and they're good to go.
‐Look at that.
Three quarter pounds of ribs,
potato salad and pinto beans.
That nice smoke ring
right there.
Good rib buddy, lightly
sauced, lightly glazed,
pull apart tender.
Potato salad's spot on.
The beans are a meal
in themselves.
All here in the parking
lot of a pawn shop.
‐That's right.
‐I like the way you roll.
Yeah, thank you.
Here's your rib plate, sir.
‐Thank you.
‐So, so, so good.
MAN:
Some of the best I've eaten
and I've eaten ribs
in 37 states.
MAN #2:
Matt does a whole lot
in that little bitty space
that he has.
‐Oh, we make it work.
‐What year is this trailer?
‐1976.
‐It's a nice one.
Thank you.
It looked a lot different
when I got it.
MAN #3: There's some prettier
carts in the city,
but I don't think
they're producing food
anywhere near the same quality.
VICEDOMINI:
The whole shabamwich.
What's in
the whole shabamwich?
All our meats
in a sandwich.
It is a taste shabam.
What's up next?
‐Our spice mix for our sausages.
‐Let's hit it.
First thing,
salt and some pepper,
paprika, Cayenne pepper,
some water.
And we're making
a pork and beef?
Our sausages are
all rib trimmings
and brisket trimmings.
Come on, dude, you can't get
any better than that.
Yeah, totally. I like to grind
it up with some fresh garlic.
And after it goes through that,
we're going to hit it
with the spice blend?
‐Yep.
And then I'm just
mixing with my hands.
‐And we're going to case this.
‐Oh, yeah.
Now, we're going to season
the other meats from the smoker.
‐Got it.
‐Pork butt and again
it's all salt and pepper
and then with the brisket,
it's salt and pepper
except we'll hit it
with a little bit of mustard.
It adds a little flavor,
a little vinegar.
That's it. It's ready
for the smoker.
‐How long for the sausage?
‐I try to go an hour and 15.
Pork is 6 to 8 hours.
‐And the brisket?
‐Around 14 hours.
‐Okay, are you ready to do this?
First, we're going
to pull the pork
and we season this
with chipotle vinegar
that we make at the cart here,
salt and sugar.
‐Sugar?
‐Oh, yeah.
I've seen a lot in my day,
I've never seen that.
So, the first thing
on the sandwich
are pickles
and pickled red onion,
pulled pork,
sausage just on top.
And will there be
nine lumberjacks
that will come
to eat this?
Yeah, there's a pound
of meat in this sandwich.
So, then we'll hit it
our barbecue sauce,
brisket on top, coleslaw.
‐Of course.
And then a giant skewer,
rib, whole shabamwich.
That's just flat‐out
ridiculous.
I don't know exactly
how to attack this.
I think it'd be better
if I just got on the tray.
This definitely
deserves a hunch.
I got any here?
‐A little.
‐A little bit?
‐Yeah.
Nothing to worry about
in front of the TV?
It's totally fine.
It makes me look good.
It makes you look good.
It's dynamite, man.
I want to tell you
right now,
the sausage
is outrageous.
Look at this, the juice
that comes out of that sausage.
The brisket's spot on.
Little vinegar chipotle
kick from the pulled pork.
Well, you're not hiding
any of the barbecue
in a bunch of sauce.
We spend a lot of time
cooking it
and we want people
to taste it, you know.
You really should.
Shabamwich.
The pulled pork
is fantastic.
The sausage is the best.
The brisket's world class,
some of the best I've ever had.
Kill it
every single time here.
The two‐meat combo.
I love it, man.
I see why you're doing so well.
‐Yeah, awesome, man.
‐Congrats.
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins
and Dives."
What do you guys
call each other?
I call him Mr. Crabs.
What do you call
the Seafood Lady?
‐Come on.
‐Miss Crabs, come on!
[ Laughter ]
Best interview in years.