Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Bawk, bawk, bawk, bawk,
bawk, bawk, bawk, bawk!
...we're firing up favorites...
A lot going on here, buddy.
...spanning
North and South America...
That is outstanding.
...like a powerhouse pub
in Charlotte...
You're doing it right,
man.
...a flavor fiesta in Cancún...
Tacos with an attitude.
...and in Houston...
This is addicting.
This is illegal.
...Argentinean empanadas
gone wild.
iAy, caramba!
That's all
right here, right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Cancún, Mexico,
in an area known
as the Avenue de Torres,
and I'm about 20 minutes
from the downtown area
to check out --
Wait a second.
They didn't have cars like this
when I rented that one.
Well, anyhow, no, I'm here
to check out a taco joint,
and not just any taco joint.
One that's got a lot
of swagger and attitude.
This is Pinchez Tacos.
Tacos ready!
They do magic
with simple ingredients.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
FIERI:
And "different" is exactly what
architect Fernando Rocha
was aiming for
when he traded in his
drafting table for a taco truck
with his fiancée,
Karen Vasconcelos.
This opens, this comes up.
-And then you have the umbrella.
-Yeah.
-It's a fun ride.
-I like that.
Let's go to the beach.
FIERI: But after a few months
on the road,
they set up stationary digs
and focused on
reinventing the taco.
This is
la casa de Pinchez Tacos.
-Yeah.
-What does it mean?
Pinchez is
the kitchen helper.
The sous-chef
is the pinchez?
-Yeah, kind of.
-What are we gonna make first?
-The Pinchez Taco.
-The one you're known for?
-Yeah.
-The Pinchez Taco -- excellent.
It's the best one.
WOMAN: It has meat,
chorizo, pork skin.
A bite will take you to heaven.
We're gonna make the...
of our pork leg.
-The marinade.
-Yeah.
-First we add vinegar.
-White vinegar.
-Cayenne.
-Okay.
-Black pepper.
-A little garlic.
Garlic. Cloves.
Cinnamon stick.
Some salt.
Then we blend it.
-It's ready.
-Very nice, Doctor.
We add lemon juice
to our mixture.
And this is just
a regular pork leg.
-The back. The ham.
-Yeah.
-How long do we leave this on?
10 to 12 hours.
Then we're gonna do our onions.
-Then we add honeybee.
-What other honey is there?
There's no, like, cow honey
or duck honey.
-There's only bee honey.
-[ Laughs ]
Then mustard.
-From the bee?
-No. The store.
[ Laughter ]
-Olive oil.
-A lot going on here, buddy.
Yeah. And some salt.
-Then we make this ready.
-Now we'll go on the grill.
-How long?
-Like 15 minutes.
-The pork?
-Pork leg. And chorizo.
Chorizo?
That's for two tacos?
Yeah. Take the pork
off from the grill.
-No finger! No finger!
-And the chorizo.
Sprinkle
some chicharrón.
-Okay.
-The onions.
-That's one Pinchez Taco.
-That's crazy.
I have never seen
a taco look like that.
-Pinchez loco.
-[ Laughs ]
This taco's
out of bounds.
It says on the sign
"Wood is an ingredient."
-It really is.
-We have four kinds of sauces.
Okay.
-A little spicy.
-Okay.
Chili machito.
Chili machete.
Cut your tongue off.
And this is the most spicy
of all -- chili habanero.
-I'll try this.
-Okay.
This is chili gringo.
That's delicious, man.
I don't know that I'm gonna
venture into the other two
'cause I don't see the
12-pack of beer on ice.
It's a very sophisticated taco.
Not normal taco-truck taco.
-Really good, man. Delicious.
-Thanks.
The chicharrón is
the crunchy in the taco.
It's fantastic.
The salsas are excellent.
It's amazing,
the atmosphere and everything.
Cancún's kind of
an interesting place.
A lot of tourists, a lot
flavors, a lot of culture.
It is worth it to go out
from the hotel zone
to go to the center of the city
so they can really
have the experience
of eating something local.
WOMAN:
Two pio pios ready!
-Why pio pio?
-It's the sound of the chicken.
"Pio, pio, pio!"
No?
Bawk, bawk, bawk, bawk,
bawk, bawk, bawk, bawk!
No.
Pio, pio, pio, pio!
What does the gallo say?
iQuiquiriqui!
No.
It's cock-a-doodle-doo!
[ Both laugh ]
iQuiquiriqui!
Hi. Welcome to "Barn Noises."
I'm Guy. Pio pio.
First, we're gonna
marinade the chicken.
This is garlic.
Lime juice.
-Okay.
-Cayenne and then salt.
-It rests 10 hours, 12 hours.
-10 hours, 12 hours.
Next we're gonna make
the pico de gallo.
Mango. Cucumber.
-Onion.
-Cilantro.
Yeah. Salt.
How about a horse?
[ Clicks tongue ]
That's more like --
[ Knocking ]
-No?
-No.
Okay, you try to go
as fast you can.
-Ready? Go.
-Ready. Go.
♪♪
[ Neighs ]
[ Laughter ]
-So, the chicken is ready.
-All right.
The tortilla.
Two tacos.
And then
the pico de gallo.
Pio, pio, pio.
Bawk, bawk!
Excellent. The chicken is nice
and tender, not overcooked.
Good wood smoke.
Nice little pico salsa there.
Bright flavors.
I thought tacos were
supposed to be tacos.
The only thing
that's similar to this --
the tortilla
and the chicken.
After that,
you change everything.
That's the real deal, man.
I love the combination
of sweet and the salty.
I say that everything
is great, but it is!
WOMAN:
Here comes the macho.
If you ever come to Cancún,
you must come
to Los Pinchez Tacos.
I think it's very brave
what you're doing.
It's creative. It's simple.
Very forward-thinking.
Tacos with an attitude.
Excellent job.
FIERI: Coming up, a bomb brewery
in Charlotte, North Carolina...
This is ridiculous
that this is work.
...where the suds come
with some gangster grub.
What you put into
one little burger
is more than a lot of people
put into their whole menu.
♪♪
So, I'm here in an area
known as NoDa,
North of Davidson Street --
and, of course, you'd know that
if you're from
Charlotte, North Carolina --
to check out a little brewery
where they're making
8 to 14 different beers
at a time,
and I'm not really here
for the beer.
Yeah, right.
I'm actually here
because the chef
is scratch-making a menu
that goes perfect
with hand-crafted beer.
Did I mention they have beer?
This is Heist Brewery.
♪♪
Chicken-and-waffle
tacos up!
Heist is definitely unique.
The beer cheese burger.
They have great beer,
and I don't think you
can find better food.
This is ridiculous
that this is work, okay?
FIERI:
But owner Kurt Hogan
wasn't always this casual
at the office.
I'm a science guy. I was
in bio-farming for a little bit.
FIERI: Then left to go back
to business school.
I was homebrewing at the time,
and I decided to make
my hobby a reality.
I met awesome people.
FIERI:
Who became partners,
like head brewer Eric Mitchell
and general manager
Spencer Farrell.
And then they added
executive chef Scott Walker.
We sampled some of his food,
and we were just like,
-"All right, this is the guy."
-Beer cheese up!
Everything's made in-house here.
And they infuse their beers
in a lot of their menu items.
FIERI: Even down to their
not-so-basic burgers.
Burger, Burger, Burger up!
The Burger, Burger, Burger
is really yummy.
Probably one of the best
burger sliders I've ever had.
I love the goat cheese
and the bacon jam.
-All right, let's start it off.
-We're gonna make our bacon jam.
Okay.
Starting off with
a little olive oil.
-Raw bacon.
-Bacon is rendered down.
We're gonna add
some minced shallots.
Got it.
Some brown sugar
and crushed red-pepper flakes.
Now in with the honey?
And then our Heist Brewery
house-made beer.
-So stir this up.
-So let this cook down?
At a low heat
for about two hours.
Really bring in
the beer flavor.
You get that
jam consistency.
I like the hoppiness.
You get a little bit of heat
in there, a little bit of sweet.
This is all on
Burger, Burger, Burger?
Yes, sir.
I'll just have that
on my hand, hand, hand.
All right. Beer barbecue sauce.
Start with an oil blend.
I'm gonna sauté some garlic
and bring out the aromatics.
You watch too many
cooking shows.
-Add a little bit of onion.
-Tomato paste. Cooking that out?
Worcestershire sauce, and then
we're gonna do brown sugar.
Yellow mustard. A little bit
of apple-cider vinegar.
-Plum tomatoes.
-And...?
-Heist Brewery...
-Okay.
...blonde ale.
Did you just do a label turn
in the middle of the show?
-I did do a label turn.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
And then...
-I Vanna White'd it.
-Don't take my lines!
Actually, if you could just grow
a goatee and bleach your hair,
you could cover
the Monday shift.
We're gonna use
our pole blender
to bring all the
ingredients together.
[ Whistles ]
For some reason,
it seems like
you make this
in a little bit larger volume.
-Sometimes.
-I'll manage the cord.
You dropped the hammer
on that!
This is all gonna
cook down how long?
-About 20 minutes.
-All right, Chef.
So, Burger, Burger, Burger.
We're gonna start
with our herb goat cheese.
Buns are house-made
brioche buns.
-Seriously?
-Yep. House --
You got that kind of time
on your hands, son?
All our own pretzels,
all our own flatbreads.
Seriously?
You got some issues.
We got our bacon jam.
-Tell me about the burger.
-Tri-blend.
-Chuck, porter, and brisket.
-Got it.
We're gonna do
our roasted tomatoes,
a little bit
of fresh arugula,
the beer barbecue,
top brioche bun.
A lot of time and energy into
this. It's good-looking.
That's legit going down.
Look at that.
It's not good unless you
have to lick your fingers.
What you put into
one little burger
is more than a lot of people
put into their whole menu.
I mean, you've got
such great flavors.
The goat cheese is cool.
It's tangy. Good acid.
'Cause you've got a lot of sweet
coming in from the bacon jam.
Love the fat
in the burger.
The bun's delicious.
It's nice, it's light.
Flavor, design,
attention to detail,
creativity.
-Well done. Great burger.
-Thank you.
Burger, Burger,
Burger up!
[ Laughing ] Definitely
not your average slider.
So, it's not like these two
need any introduction,
but this is a "Triple D" OG
sitting right over here.
This is Greg.
Now, he was from The Penguin.
Now he has Pinky's.
And then this character --
Well, you've not only
seen him on "Triple D."
You've seen him
on "Triple G."
So we all know George
from Krazy Fish.
How are these guys doing
on their burger?
Very good. Love goat cheese,
tomato jam.
Good pairing
with this dark beer, too.
Microbreweries now
are getting so built up,
they're pretty high-end.
This still seems like
a funky little joint
that a couple dudes
are running.
It is. It's a great joint.
You come here,
have a great beer.
Great people around.
Tasty food.
WOMAN:
You don't always find breweries
that have great food
along with great beer.
So, here's the deal.
We're in Charlotte,
North Carolina,
hanging out
at Heist Brewery.
Chef and I just knocked
out Burger, Burger, Burger.
-What are we making next?
-Our duck-confit flatbread.
This is the best place
in town for flatbreads.
The duck is fantastic.
Really unique flavor.
We'll see you back
in a minute, minute, minute.
Minute, minute, minute.
It usually takes
three minutes until you go --
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're hanging out at...
Heist Brewery.
Charlotte, North Carolina.
Of all the breweries here, this
definitely has the best kitchen.
Do you girls, uh,
normally go to breweries?
We are from
Milwaukee, Wisconsin,
so we grew up with them.
Oh, that's right.
Come on. Milwaukee?
That's like giving
the blessing on a brewery.
-And how's the food?
-Excellent.
Flatbread's delicious.
Crispy.
-Great flavors. Yep.
-Duck confit.
WALKER:
Duck-confit flatbread up!
MAN:
Duck is not a common protein,
but here it fits well
with the overall menu.
Flatbread with
the duck confit?
Yes, sir.
All right. Flatbread.
High-gluten,
organic bread flour.
-Big bowl.
Into a smaller vessel.
5 bucks -- something
goes on the floor.
Just start mailing
in the money now.
-Yep! Geez. What a mess.
-Oh, yep.
All right. Salt.
Heist Brewery beer.
Water.
While the mix is running, you're
gonna add a little bit of oil.
So, 5 to 10 minutes,
it pulls away
from the side of the bowl.
-Yep.
-Cut it into portions.
And then let it proof
in the walk-in overnight.
Now we're getting to
the confit of the duck?
Whoa!
The whole duck!
-Whole duck.
-You gangster.
-Salt and pepper.
-A little bit of garlic.
Yep. Rubbed in.
-Duck fat.
-Nothing else?
Beauty's in
the simplicity.
We let the duck
speak for itself.
Well, it's not doing
much of that now.
It's not quacking
at all.
Not what
it's quacked up to be.
Nope. We're gonna
wrap it with foil.
And we're gonna do this
in the wood oven?
A minimum of five hours.
Pull it out,
shred the meat.
Then you use the leftover
rendered skin and bones
-to make your next confit.
-Yes, sir.
A nicely rolled out
piece of flatbread.
We're gonna put a little bit
of mozzarella cheese.
-Okay.
-We got duck confit next.
Nice little bit of duck
in every bite.
Pickled shallots.
-Our barbecue sauce?
-House beer barbecue sauce.
Got it. How long
is this gonna take?
Two minutes is what
we're shooting for.
Oven's running
about 650?
-Yep.
-Bring it.
That's nice and thin.
So, duck confit.
Some fried shallots.
A little fresh chives.
More barbecue sauce?
Just to set the flavor off.
You know what?
If I didn't know better,
with the richness and tanginess
and the saltiness
of what you're doing,
you might be inspiring people
to drink more beer.
I'm going out on a limb,
and I don't know
if you've thought of this.
It's a side thought.
It's delicious.
The way
you make your dough,
the way you put it
together, it's dynamite.
The confit duck
is just enough.
That's a great dish.
You're putting
as much time and energy
and enthusiasm and attitude
towards the food
as they are over there
making the beer.
-Yes.
-You're doing it right, man.
They got to love you here.
-Thank you, Chef.
-Congratulations, man.
MAN:
The duck flatbread.
The bread is crisp and flaky.
Their barbecue sauce complements
the duck confit perfectly,
and then the fried
shallots on top -- awesome.
You're fine
with inducting them
into the Charlotte
"Triple D" family?
-Oh, yeah.
-Hands down.
-Cuban with fries.
-You guys are way too young.
This is ridiculous that you
get to drink beer and work.
-Heard that.
-And your chef --
-This guy is dangerous.
-For sure.
Keep it up. I mean, try to keep
the stress level down.
We'll do what we can.
FIERI: Up next, meet the
Empanada Emperor of Houston...
And you are the maestro
of the crazy band.
...cooking straight from
the heart for over 40 years.
-Give me a hug.
-We're gonna hug it out!
See you in a minute.
There we go.
-Do you have kids?
-No.
-Do you have a wife?
-I'm working on that.
-What's her name?
-Kiffany.
-Kiffany?
-Yep.
-She your fiancée?
-Not yet. I have to ask.
You just got to find
the right time to do it.
Well, I mean, no time like
the present, in my opinion.
Uh, you could be right.
So, will you marry me?
-Yes!
-Oh, my goodness!
♪♪
So, I'm here on the southwest
side of Houston, Texas,
in an area known as Westchase.
Now, this is where you'll find
all the big power companies,
a bunch of hospitals,
and a mom-and-pop joint
where they're doing
over 80 different varieties
of an Argentinean specialty.
This is it -- The Original
Marini's Empanada House.
♪♪
Two Chicken Diablos
coming up, por favor!
The empanadas are delicious.
And then I have the two
Nacho Machos with the avocado.
FIERI: How do you describe
what it is?
It's a fried pie,
kinda, sorta...
Stuffed with beef
or chicken or vegetables.
Everybody likes them.
They're so good.
FIERI:
Could be talking about owners
Pelusa and Marcello Marini,
high-school sweethearts
from Argentina
who came to the States
to jump-start their career.
In 1970, we came
looking for a job in TV.
I'm a journalist
by profession.
Then somebody gave me
the opportunity
to do the first talk show
in the Spanish language
on an English TV station.
"Hola Amigos."
-But in the meantime...
-We're making empanadas.
FIERI: They opened
their first joint in 1971,
which means they're full-blown
empanada experts by now.
What makes
a really good empanada?
The dough is our secret,
from the grandma.
Okay, we're gonna
make the dough first?
Yes.
This little mixer
does all the work?
-Plus my hands.
-All-purpose flour?
-We're gonna put a little...
-Baking soda.
Baking soda.
He knows!
-Salt.
-The shortening.
-Water.
-How long?
-It's about 4 minutes.
-Okay.
Pull a piece off, and then
we run it through the sheeter?
-Yes. You see?
-I got it.
Now you do it.
And then another one.
-Come on. Let's go.
-Go! Go!
We do Texas-style.
Bigger in Texas?
So, nice and thin.
-Yes.
-Let's go make an empanada.
FIERI: And if you want
real-deal Argentinean,
well, you know it's
got to be the Beef Gaucho.
We're gonna make the Beef
Gaucho filling with picadillo.
"Picadillo."
-I got it right? Okay.
-Yes.
First, the ground meet.
-Oregano. Comino. Cumin.
-I got you.
-Salt.
-There we go.
A little pepper.
Cebolla.
-Yeah. Hey!
-Hey!
-Spanish Paprika.
-Little chili flake.
-We let it simmer a little bit.
-And then we let it cool?
-Yes. Señor...
-Fieri. Fieri.
-Italian?
-Yes.
Si. Oh.
Molto bene.
Okay, now we make
the chimichurri.
Wine vinegar.
A little bit of olive oil.
Fresh parsley.
Sweet basil.
-Ajo.
-Un poquito de ajo.
Crushed red pepper.
[ Whirring ]
Okay.
Fantastic.
I love you.
We hug a lot
of this show today.
-Let's make one.
-Do it.
Wow. Right! Olives.
-Fold it in half.
-I got it.
We're gonna hug again,
I can already tell.
Press, press!
Pull a little bit.
Yes!
This is the problem.
-What?
-The big ring!
[ Laughter ]
That hurt.
When they get to this point,
where do we go?
-To the fryer?
-Yes. We cover it with this.
Oh, really?
You keep it down with one?
Sí. 3 to 4 minutes.
Okay. Look at that.
Beautiful.
That's good. The dough has got
really nice texture.
But it's nice and light.
Oh, yeah. The filling --
just the right amount of spice.
Love the brininess of the little
bit of olive in there.
The chimichurri
changes it all.
-Mmm!
-Yes.
There's a good amount
of basil in it,
so you get a little bit
of that sweetness.
That's really good.
We're gonna hug it out!
See you in a minute.
There we go.
Hello.
Two Beef Gaucho.
The chimichurri is wonderful.
You can just taste
how fresh it is.
Is it like a burrito
and a ravioli?
Yes.
It's really good.
So, this is
this Clebourne family,
good friends of mine
here in Texas.
This is amazing.
-Tons of different flavors.
-Yeah.
When you look up
on the menu,
all the different options
that they offer --
WOMAN: Do you know how many
options there are?
I think they do over
80 different options.
-Yeah.
-That's crazy.
There's a huge variety,
and they're all good.
FIERI:
Like the Chicken Diablo,
which combines Italian tomato
sauce with an avocado topper.
It's a pesto avocado
meets chimichurri.
Mmm! Delicious.
The avocado
all goes together
with the sweetness of the tomato
and the basil.
Tender chicken. And again,
the rocking empanada dough.
It's very flavorful
but not spicy.
FIERI: No, they're leaving
the heat up to a fiery favorite.
-Hot Tia Maria.
Oil. Fresh onions.
Poblano pepper.
We put some beef.
The jus? Okay.
So, the pan sauce
from when we cooked it.
-Garlic.
-This is the basil.
Serrano pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Very hot.
Fresh tomatoes.
Okay.
And we let that cook down?
-Yes.
-After it cools down...
Then we're gonna
make the empanadas.
Then we make
the empanada with it.
This is Tia Maria.
Hot.
I can definitely smell
the chilies in there.
Mmm.
Oh, that's good.
I want you to think
about the best shredded beef
with a good amount
of spice.
-And this is the...
-Mucho Macho.
Mucho Macho.
-[ Gasps ]
-Hot?
Yes.
That's hot.
[ Whistles ]
That is outstanding!
It's not so spicy that
you don't taste everything.
That right there is
one of the best empanadas
I've ever had
in my life.
-You are Superman.
-Oh, this is addicting.
-This is illegal actually.
-I don't want to see that!
[ Gasps ]
iEl gringo loco!
iAy, caramba!
The Hot Tia Maria
with the chimichurri sauce.
That rush and flavor
just comes at you.
Got a little bit
of heat?
Yeah, when you got hair like
that, though, it doesn't matter.
You could do anything.
Fantastic.
It's just great.
All the crazy is real,
and it comes out
in the empanada.
And you are the maestro
of the crazy band.
You are fantastic.
Watch out for this guy, huh?
There we go!
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
-What does a pig say?
-Oink.
-How about a duck?
-Quack, quack!
-How does a dolphin sound?
-[ Squeaks ]
-[ Smooches ]
-[ Laughs ]
It must have been us.