Hey, I'm Guy Fieri
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown!
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
This trip...
Thermalize!
...we're cooking up
all kinds of meat...
Don't eat for a week, and then
come down and have this.
...stacked, pied,
[chuckle] and fried.
I might have
to try another one.
Like in a Colorado
craft brewhouse...
That crushes it.
...serving up a righteous
menu with a mission.
Aw, man!
That is so awesome.
Plus, a Dallas pizza joint...
I can't shovel that
in my face fast enough.
...tossin' in
a true Texas twist...
[ Whistling ]
...and a funky spot
in Scottsdale, Arizona.
I'll have that
on a shoe.
...rockin' and rollin'
[chuckle] real-deal Vietnamese.
I could literally go
into a food coma,
just eating these.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
I'm here in Longmont, Colorado,
just outside of Boulder,
to check out a place
with an amazing story.
So you got this married couple
that are social workers
and they've got a business,
helping place
intellectually disabled adults
with jobs.
All of a sudden,
they have this idea:
"Why don't we open
our own restaurant,
create jobs for them?
It'll be incredible."
You think that's incredible?
Wait till you try the menu.
This is Samples.
♪♪
Table 42, Bacon Bleu.
Samples is an amazing place.
Here's the Food Truck
Mac & Cheese.
It's more than
just a restaurant.
MAN:
You support a great cause.
You get amazing food.
It's really just like
the best of both worlds.
FIERI:
And those two worlds
happily collided
when Mark and Carmen Sample
created this comfort-food
and craft-beer joint
with a mission in mind.
We make everything
from scratch.
Partly 'cause
I don't know any better,
-[Laughing]
-partly because
those inefficiencies
create jobs.
So, every day, we have
individuals with disabilities
that are hosting, busing,
dishwashing, prep cooking,
so over 40 people
are currently employed.
-Get out.
-Yeah.
CJ, I got those jerk
wings coming to 24.
The food!
Oh, my gosh!
The food is good!
Some flavors that you
don't see everywhere else.
Got a poutine burger,
medium rare.
Poutine burger is massive.
MAN:
They put the fries, the gravy,
the cheese curds.
It's amazing. [laughs]
All right. What are we into?
What are we making first?
Our beef stock, that's gonna
go into the poutine gravy
for the poutine burger.
-Poutine is this nice,
big, rich gravy
on top of French fries.
First, we have
roasted-up beef bones.
That's where we're getting
our depth of flavor.
Got our water here,
our mirepoix, bay leaves.
-Wow!
-Peppercorn.
Red wine, thyme.
A healthy amount
of garlic.
We're gonna
bring it to a boil,
and then we're gonna
let it simmer overnight.
Strain it, and that'll
be just one part
of this gravy that we're
putting together?
Exactly, and the other
part's gonna be
that short-rib
braising liquid.
-Gimme the breakdown.
-We're gonna take short ribs,
a little oil, a little salt,
a little pepper.
Gonna brown 'em off in the oven.
-And then?
We're gonna add everything
else to it for our braising.
We got honey first,
a whole lot of garlic,
a little apple-cider vinegar.
I love all the songs
you're singing right now.
Little more salt,
little black pepper.
Bay leaves!
You love
your bay leaves.
Tomato paste,
red wine.
♪♪
Thyme.
And the mirepoix.
In the oven,
strain the jus.
Short rib's going
off to another dish?
-Exactly.
-I like the way you roll.
We've got our beef stock
and our braising liquids.
-Got it.
-We're gonna bring 'em together
with a cornstarch slurry.
Stir in the slurry.
Now while that tightens up,
we go to fries?
-Exactly.
-So you handcut your fries?
Soak 'em in water,
blanch 'em,
and then we're gonna
cook 'em off for service.
Now we're gonna
deep-fry the curds.
Yeah. First, we're gonna
make our dredge.
We got flour,
cornstarch,
chili powder.
You know that cheese
curds are good
just by themselves?
You don't have to fry 'em.
They do work that way, but they
get so gooey and perfect.
Black pepper,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion.
Bunch of salt.
Mix that together.
Take our cheese curds,
soak in the buttermilk,
got our good dredge out.
Now we go to the fryer.
[ Sizzling ]
All right.
We're gonna start with our
shallot dressing we made.
How about we just cover
the things
you didn't make, okay?
So we didn't make
the tongs.
We didn't hammer these
out of
-[Laughing]
-cold steel.
Then we're gonna go with...
-Housemade pickles.
...a few pickles we made.
Got our burger comin'
off the grill.
Then we're gonna go
cheese curds first.
Now we got our fries,
throw those right on top.
Got that beautiful gravy
that we've made.
♪♪
And that is your
poutine burger.
♪♪
Tremendous flavor.
The patty's cooked right.
There's more gravy on here
than humanly consumable.
♪♪
The pickles are the key because
you gotta have something
to cut all the richness of this.
♪♪
Fried cheese curds: spot-on.
And the fries are gangster.
This poutine gravy,
that crushes it.
Don't eat for a week,
and then
come down and have this.
-[Laughs]
-The poutine burger.
-Thank you.
I've never had a burger
with cheese curds before.
I love it.
-That's my good buddy Darren;
his wife, Anna.
Tell me what you think.
The flavors that are
in this
beef-stock sauce here,
very good.
Jerk wings
goin' to the roof!
MAN:
The food is as good here
as you're gonna get
anywhere else.
It's just nice to know
that you can come here
and support people that are
doing something really good.
Brandon,
you run the front desk.
Yes. Sometimes I prep
on special occasions.
This is a good
place to work.
You learned a lot of things
you never did before.
-And you get good.
The people that receive
services from us
are the most
consistent employees
anybody will ever have.
We work with a lot
of other restaurants, too,
where we go and we do
their dishwashing
or their prep cooking
or their hosting.
-Aw, man!
-Yeah.
-That is so awesome!
-[Laughing]
It's really been amazing
to see this restaurant
blossoming to where it's become.
Great place to stop in
for a beer or a burger
or a Korean BBQ Sandwich.
'Cause it goes right along
with the poutine.
We're just leaving Canada,
heading on down to Korea
when we come back.
♪♪
Welcome back to "Triple D"
in downtown Longmont, Colorado,
right outside of Boulder.
We're hanging out at Samples.
MAN:
It's not just another
restaurant down the street.
There's a mission
tied behind it.
They're giving great
jobs for people
with intellectual disabilities.
FIERI:
And, along with the great cause
comes killer culinary
and plenty of craft beer.
And for every beer,
there's an excellent dish
that it pairs with.
-So many different flavors,
different worldly items.
Korean BBQ sandwich.
The meat is really
nicely marinated.
And then you have this
pop of the peppers
and the kimchi that
just sort of offset it.
All right. So we're going
to our Korean BBQ Sandwich.
-Boneless short ribs.
-Slice those down.
And then we build
the marinade?
-Exactly.
-Okay.
I've got tamari,
gluten-free soy sauce.
-Okay.
-Sugar.
Lime juice.
Scallions.
Got our garlic.
Chopped ginger,
sesame oil,
chili garlic,
and some water.
How long are we gonna
let those ribs go in?
3 hours is plenty enough.
That's gonna be enough?
Okay, home slice.
Home slice. Short rib.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Home slice. No?
I thought it was funny.
All right.
What do you got for me?
-All right. Now we're gonna make
our kimchi for the
Korean BBQ sandwich.
-Okay.
-We're gonna start
with some cabbage.
It's been salted,
soaked, rinsed.
Next, some shredded carrot,
soy sauce,
sugar.
Honey.
Chopped ginger,
garlic.
We'll add chili garlic sambal,
and then the fish sauce.
Fish sauce
makes the funk.
Mix it all together.
And how long are we
letting that set?
For about 5 days.
All right.
Make it happen, homey.
Grab our ribs, hit 'em for
about a minute on each side.
Start with our hoagie roll.
-Okay.
-Our pickled peppers.
Kimchi.
We got our ribs.
At about a perfect medium
on those.
♪♪
A little sriracha mayo.
-I like it.
-Side of those handcut fries.
That's a good-looking
sandwich, buddy.
♪♪
The meat's cooked perfectly.
Short rib is nice and lean
and mean and tender
and has got
the right flavor.
♪♪
I could just have a plate
of the kimchi
and the meat, little bulgogi.
And the theory that
you're gonna get a beer
that's gonna pair great
with it, that's the beauty.
Korean BBQ, Rose!
The kimchi gives that
extra little kick
that you aren't
necessarily expecting.
This sandwich
is really good.
I can't wait
to come back.
-Is it that kind of place?
-It's that kind of place.
One of the best places
in all of Colorado, hands down.
What y'all doing, how you're
treating your team members,
how you're working
with your community,
you got a great program, man.
Dude, you're awesome.
I'm impressed.
Thank you.
Up next...
I'm bringing some backup
in Scottsdale, Arizona...
BOTH:
Would I? Would I?
...to a joint firing up
a hotpot...
Smoking, sizzling.
...packed with
knockout flavors.
I'd eat that
till I fall asleep.
Hi, Grandma Bev.
It's Guy, hanging out
with your grandson.
Awesome, by the way.
Loves the cheese curds,
preps on Mondays.
Kisses.
Was that a KISS shoutout
in the middle
of my tribute to Grandma?
[ Laughter ]
Huh?
-I love you, Grandma!
[ Laughs ]
[ Beep ]
♪♪
So I'm here
in Scottsdale, Arizona,
and I'm just like you guys.
I roll into a town.
I don't know where to eat, so I
call up one of my chef buddies,
a "Triple D" OG
and "Guy's Grocery Game" judge,
the one and only
Chef Aaron May.
What do we got?
-Amazing story.
Legit food.
You know I wouldn't
steer you wrong.
We shall see.
This is Slanted Rice.
♪♪
Chicken beef.
WOMAN:
I've been to many
Vietnamese restaurants.
This is my favorite.
I wish I could
make this at home.
They use authentic spices
and it just makes everything
very aromatic and flavorful.
Dragon Lady
spring roll, please.
Hue is one of the most
fun-loving, nice people.
FIERI:
With an incredible story.
We left in '79.
On a boat, that's sinking.
And this Japanese
vessel rescued us.
We got to America: 1981.
And started sharing the flavors
of Hue Tran's homeland.
Our family's been
in the restaurant industry
for a long time.
-What type of food is this?
90 percent Vietnamese,
10 percent fusion.
The flavors:
amazing stuff.
Crispy clay pot, please.
I always love getting
the crispy clay pot.
So delicious.
It's got chicken and vegetables
and an amazing sauce
and the rice at the bottom
is absolutely unbelievable.
This is really
my favorite dish here.
What's the first thing
we're gonna make?
Okay. The sauce.
Sugar,
soy sauce,
sesame oil, pepper,
oyster sauce.
Okay. I'll have that
on a shoe.
[laughs]
The heat of the pepper
and the sugar balance:
amazing.
Now you wanna cook
jasmine rice.
FIERI: Okay.
-Put it over the stove.
And we can go
direct-flame with that?
Mm-hmm.
It takes 9 to 10 minutes.
-Okay.
-Then we'll jump over here.
-Let's see it.
-Okay. Regular canola oil.
-Chicken breast.
-Okay.
Some garlic.
Sweet soy.
This is bok choy
and shiitake mushroom.
And the whole time,
we have been blasting
the rice over there
in the clay pot.
-Yes.
-I'm nervous about the rice.
I'm nervous
about the rice.
Well, calm down, guys.
Smoking, sizzling.
That looks amazing.
Cilantro?
All right.
♪♪
That's a legit pot
right there.
♪♪
The sauce is so good.
The quick sauté on the
chicken is really nice.
Yeah.
It's tender. It's juicy.
You pick up the garlic.
I'd eat that
till I fall asleep.
The real gem: when
you get to the bottom
-Yeah.
-and you get the rice,
that's had a chance
to kind of like dehydrate.
-Really? Oh, well, thank you.
-This is really done well.
My only advice is, when you
come down to try this,
is order your own.
[ Laughter ]
'Cause this is
definitely not working.
Crispy rice in a clay pot
with chicken.
It's the right amount
of spices.
Crispy rice at the bottom
truly makes the dish.
It's so full of flavor.
I don't think people get
how much of a destination
Scottsdale, Phoenix,
this area is for great food.
In the time
I've been here,
the food scene
has exploded.
And you can't forget all the
crazy "Triple D" characters
we run into down here.
From Andreoli's,
Giovanni and Francesca.
Are you able to make
enough prosciutto
for everybody
that comes to visit?
Flies away very fast.
It flies away.
Let's talk about
Slanted Rice. What do you
think of the place?
-Very good.
-Superfresh. Really good.
-Beautiful.
-Lemongrass Brussels sprouts.
The food
is like tremendous.
I've had pretty much
everything on the menu.
Crispy pork egg rolls.
The crispy egg roll
is fantastic.
The sauce, I don't even know
what's in it,
but it's unbelievable.
When you dip in
crispy pork egg rolls,
you want vinaigrette.
-Let's see it.
Put some sugar in.
Warm water.
Fish sauce.
So, the last one,
I put some vinegar.
-I like it.
-Now we're gonna make
the egg rolls?
-We have ground pork.
-Got it.
-Glass noodles.
-Rice noodles.
-Mm-hmm.
-Do you chop the noodles,
just so it mixes better?
-Mm-hmm.
And then some carrots,
green onions,
yellow onions, ear mushrooms.
-Wood ear mushrooms?
-Wood ear?
-Yeah, yeah. I love it.
-Would I?
-Wood ear.
BOTH:
Would I? Would I?
A little chicken
bouillon, sugar.
Can't go
without the sugar.
Fish sauce
and some pepper.
I feel like you could almost do
anything with this now, Hue.
You can make dumplings.
You can make
-You can, of course.
-spring rolls.
Put it in a soup.
-Pork-and-noodle soup.
-Mm-hmm.
So now we take
a spring-roll pastry.
You're finding the more
moist one at the bottom?
-Yeah, yeah.
-I like the way you put it
out there flat, and then
you squeeze it back in.
Does that help keep all the
-Of course.
air pockets and everything
out of there?
Exactly. You keep on
pushing it back.
You're keeping it
really tight.
Egg wash? Make sure it sticks.
-Yeah. Mm-hmm.
And that's all
she rolled.
-You're done.
-That's all she rolled.
All right.
Now we deep-fry them?
That's it.
-Okay. Two for Guy.
None for Aaron.
Fish-sauce vinaigrette.
So I have pickled carrots
and daikon here,
egg rolls.
So you wanna put the mint
along the way lettuce,
wrap it around, and dip
in the fish sauce.
It's like
a lettuce wrap.
I'm camouflaging
my egg roll.
Makes it healthier.
♪♪
Mmm!
-Good job.
I love egg rolls that
are all business
and that's all business:
a lot of pork,
a lot of seasoning,
really crispy.
The texture of the glass noodle,
too, is just dynamite.
But the whole kicker is
this roll it in the lettuce
and hit it
with the mint.
So good.
And then you get
this sweet tang.
I might have to try
another one.
Oh, gosh!
[ Laughter ]
This is legit.
I could literally go
into a food coma,
just eating these.
♪♪
Outstanding.
So crunchy and flavor-packed.
The dipping sauce,
it's got a little sweet,
but a little spicy.
Vegetarian pho.
I don't think anyone can outdo
the flavors that they do.
You just can't get enough of it.
The fun thing about
this place is
it's really accessible.
You keep it real.
You do what you do,
and you do it great.
That's why Aaron
recommended it.
-Oh, thank you.
-Good job, brother man.
-Thanks, man.
-I'm impressed.
Nicely done, sister.
Coming up...a not-your-everyday
Dallas spot...
[garbled]
More sugar --
...mashing up pizza
with barbecue...
It far exceeds
my expectations.
...and topping things off
with a crunch.
How many pizzas have you
had with chips on it?
I haven't had enough.
I'll tell you that much.
♪♪
I don't know about
your family, but mine?
We're always having the big
debate on what's for dinner.
Now, if it was up to the kids,
we'd always have Chinese food.
But let's say
that you want barbecue.
Well, then somebody
wants pizza.
Well, listen:
If you find yourself
in downtown Dallas, Texas,
don't worry.
I got a joint for ya.
It's barbecue on pizza.
This is Tutta's Pizza.
♪♪
SCOTT:
8-inch Smokey Pig, ready.
This pizza is amazing.
Different pizza from any pizza
you've ever had.
I got a Hot Chick
pizza ready, guys.
How do you take a food that
so many people get right
and make it even better?
FIERI:
How about adding
a Texas Two-Step?
That's what Jeremy Scott's
been doing
ever since he left the IT biz
and combined his love
for backyard cookouts
with his passion for pies.
Pizza needs to be dynamic.
It needs to be unique,
so I decided I wanna do
Texas-style barbecue.
I need some more chopped
brisket for the Texan.
If there was anything
that I came
and tried the first time,
it would have to be...?
Definitely the Texan.
The soft brisket with
the crunchy, like the crust,
and you're just like,
"Oh, my god. This is so good.
I want like 10 pieces."
-What are we making first?
-So we're gonna make
our housemade barbecue sauce.
We're gonna cook it right here
on the char-grillers.
-No burners?
No, I have a griddle top
and I have a char-griller.
Why do I need a burner?
-Let's go ahead
and make the sauce.
-All right.
Tomato sauce,
lemon juice,
real tomato ketchup,
granulated garlic,
light-brown sugar,
black pepper, white vinegar,
-[Whistles]
of the distilled kind.
-Cumin?
-Cayenne pepper.
A whole mess of
Worcestershire-shire sauce.
-That's right.
-Your honor, your honor.
That cooks down
for 30 minutes.
Next up, we're gonna
make the house dry rub.
So we're gonna go down first
with the light-brown sugar,
the cayenne pepper.
-BOTH: Paprika.
Black pepper, garlic salt,
oregano, onion salt,
white pepper,
-Okay.
-chili powder, cumin.
There you go. Untrimmed,
big, fat brisket.
-Ready to go.
-That's a generous dry rub.
Fantastic.
Drop it in the smoker.
12 hours at 210.
-What kind of wood?
-Mesquite wood.
-Bring it out.
-Let it come down
[ Sizzling ]
to a nice-enough temperature
that we can pull
or chop it,
and then rethermalize it
on the pizza.
-We what?
-You're bringing it back
to temperature.
-Warming it up?
-Yes, sir.
-Who says rethermalize?
Oh, IT guys.
♪♪
That's tasty brisket.
So we made
the dough.
Technically, it's
a Roman-style pizza crust.
It's a little more crunchy.
-So it's gonna have
a little chew. It's gonna
have a little deck to it.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay. Did you cook at home
a lot before you were
a restauranteur?
I was a latchkey kid,
so I did cook a lot.
Did you have the key on
a string around your neck?
-Carried it on my drumstick bag.
-You're a drummer?
And singer-songwriter.
We play a lot.
-You do it all?
-Yeah.
Semolina.
-Culinary ball bearings.
Culinary
ball bearings!
That's about 16 inches.
Homemade barbecue sauce.
Like that vinegar
in the barbecue sauce.
Mozzarella cheese, down with
the chopped brisket,
sliced red onion.
-Okay.
Get some of that sweetness.
Gotta add on some
peperoncini peppers to it
so you can get a little
bit of tartness
and a little bit of heat,
and then we're ready
to fire this off
about 4 minutes.
Three, two, one.
Rethermalize!
[ Horns tooting ]
That's when it tells
you it's done,
is the trumpeting horns?
I mean, you couldn't
give me some Metallica?
We got a Texan pizza.
♪♪
This is how you serve it,
on a sheet tray?
-Yes, sir.
-[Whistles]
I like how thin the crust is.
Good texture
on the bottom.
♪♪
Hmm.
This really is a nice
juxtaposition
between good barbecue
and really good pizza,
and the great thing is,
your brisket isn't supersmoky.
♪♪
Where you really prevail
is the peperoncini.
The acid cutting through
the sweetness
and all that heavy weight that
you're getting from the brisket,
it kind of cleanses
the palate a little.
It far exceeds my expectations.
Nicely done.
-Thank you.
The brisket is a lot of flavor.
Blend of savory
and sweet.
FIERI: And a little
bit of spice.
-Little bit of spice.
It's perfect.
Question is: have you seen
Jeremy play music yet?
-Does he play music great?
-BOTH: Absolutely.
When he put this place in,
he made sure that the
sound system was set up
and that he could
actually perform.
♪ The stars ♪
What's he do better,
music or pizza?
Both.
All right.
I got a Chipper pizza!
The Chipper's
a really fun pizza.
It's a chicken pizza with chips,
for that inner 8-year-old.
So, next, we're gonna make
the roasted chicken
that's gonna go
on our Chipper pizza.
'Cause it makes you happy,
you'll be chipper?
'Cause it has chips on it.
We're just gonna make
a simple little spice mix
to go on the roasted chicken:
sea salt, black pepper,
garlic salt, and garlic powder.
♪♪
Little bit of olive oil.
-And then we're gonna go
into the superoven.
What temp?
-190.
-190?
Till it gets to 165.
165. Pull it out.
Let it cool. Chop it up.
Next?
-We're gonna make the
housemade barbecue ranch.
Mayonnaise, of course.
-Copious amounts.
Buttermilk,
ranch seasoning.
Take our homemade barbecue
sauce that we made earlier.
You take this
delicious ranch,
jack it up with barbecue sauce?
-That's right.
The longer this sets up,
the better it's gonna be.
Yes, sir.
That works for me.
All right.
Our homemade barbecue sauce.
Mozzarella cheese.
Our roasted chicken.
-Nice and moist.
-And some pieces of bacon.
Boil it down in its own fat,
it's much better than
just crisping it up.
-In the oven.
-We're doing it about 560.
Four minutes.
[ Horns tooting ]
So we got our housemade chips,
our homemade dry rub.
You made the chips?
-Yes, sir.
-They're great chips.
Spread 'em out on our pizza.
Barbecue ranch drizzle.
Our Chipper pizza.
♪♪
Ah-ah.
The crunchification
makes it.
It's so good.
It now makes me realize that
all pizza needs a little crunch.
Just texturally takes the pizza
to a whole nother level.
Chicken's moist;
chicken's tender.
Right amount of barbecue sauce,
right amount of cheese.
The drizzle at the end, without
question, really delicious.
♪♪
I can't shovel that
in my face fast enough.
-Oh!
-Here's your large Chipper.
The chicken is done
just perfect.
The sauce he puts on it actually
gives it a really good kick.
How many pizzas have you
had with chips on it?
I haven't had enough.
I'll tell you that much.
-Right?
-That's gonna be the new move.
I got a Feelin' Aloha
pizza, 16.
Excited to see what other
new creations he comes up with.
This is completely
unorthodox.
You're making sauce
on a grill.
-Mm-hmm.
-[Whistling]
You take all of your smarts,
and you put it into play
in this place.
Congrats, man.
-Thank you, Guy.
♪♪
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry!
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country!
I'll be looking
for you next week,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
[ Applause ]
Killed it.
Oh, you wanna arm wrestle?
No!
[ Laughter ]
I'll just give the money.
-Come on!
-No way.
I'm not taking against that.
Look at that thing!
No way!
Standing down!
That. Was awesome.