Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Imitates horse chomping ]
...we're headed off
the beaten path...
It's a food truck, sir.
It's not a space shuttle.
...to discover
new territory in Flavortown.
I am blown away.
From surprising south‐of‐
the‐border in Virginia...
One of my new favorite
Mexican dishes.
...to masterful
mash‐ups in Los Angeles.
I'm really
just trying to shovel
as much of this in my mouth
as I can.
And in Maui...
And there's more.
...a mobile culinary
adventure...
It's overwhelming
just how cool you are.
...playing
righteous recipe roulette.
That's how you get it done,
ladies and gentlemen.
[ Chuckles ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins &amp; Dives."
♪♪♪
You got to love Maui.
I mean, there's never
a bad view.
Especially if you're
a food truck
where you can set up business
anywhere you want.
So I'm here to see a chef
that's all about farm‐to‐table.
I mean, this dude is literally
going to the farms himself
every other day.
And if I have one
more person tell me
I got to check this place out,
I might just lose it.
This is it ‐‐
Maui Fresh Streatery.
♪♪♪
KAWAKAMI: Short rib loco moco
with sous vide.
Everything that comes out
that window is amazing.
Sautéed mahi, shiitake
ponzu cream sauce.
Always really
unique combinations.
Fiery eggplant
caponata quesadilla.
Every other week, we get a new,
innovative, exciting menu.
You basically just say,
"Where I show up
and when you show up,
it's what we have to offer."
Exactly. So we have
20 menus that we go
through throughout the year.
FIERI:
And Chef Kyle Kawakami bases
each of those menus
on a different global cuisine.
Shelly, your okonomiyaki.
A okonomiyaki is a traditional
Japanese street pancake.
This is better than the one
I had in Japan.
Really?
It has lots of elements
included in it ‐‐
shrimp and pork.
All right,
so let's do this, Chef.
So we got our pork butt,
and we're gonna make
our marinade really quick.
Miso paste, soy, sake.
You got two of them on.
[ Laughs ]
Sugar and a little
bit of ginger.
Okay,
so the marinade goes on.
Give it a quick massage.
Wrap this.
Put this in the chill overnight.
Goes into our oven,
350 degrees for 3 hours.
Then we'll pull it out
and shred it.
Beautiful. What's up next?
‐Okonomi sauce.
It's one of the two sauces
that the pancake comes with.
Okay.
We got some ketchup,
some local,
organic honey,
Worcestershire sauce.
‐Worcestershire‐shire‐shire.
‐Worcestershire sauce.
And a little soy.
And that's ready to go.
Okay.
Next up?
The batter
for the okonomiyaki.
‐What is this?
‐Yamaimo.
It's a Japanese
mountain yam.
Like a daikon with
a texture of jicama,
but the slime of okra.
Mmm.
Because it has so
much starch in it,
it adds the crispness
to the batter.
So it's gonna add
Christmas to it.
‐Chr‐‐ Christmas?
‐Christmas.
Crisp‐ness.
‐Crisp‐ness.
[ Chuckles ]
Let's peel this.
Then we're gonna
go and cut that.
Then let's go straight
to the blender.
A little water.
That's it.
‐That's nuts, bro.
Find our mixing bowl.
‐A. p. flour.
Eggs. Dashi, which is water
and soup stock.
Salt.
‐Okay.
And our yamaimo puree.
All right, Chef,
batter's made.
Now we're gonna go ahead
and make our pancake.
Shredded, local cabbage,
a little bit of bay shrimp.
Some of the roasted,
shredded pork,
a nice ladle of our batter.
Stirry, stirry.
Onto the flattop.
Beautiful.
We're not done yet.
‐And there's more.
‐Yep.
A little bit of bacon.
'Cause bacon makes
everything better.
You cook this
on one side, flip it.
Flip it.
Takes about 8 to 10 minutes.
We'll put that right
in our plate there.
‐Okay.
‐Two sauces.
‐All right.
‐The Okonomi sauce that we made.
Kewpie mayonnaise.
Kewpie mayonnaise is
a Japanese mayonnaise ‐‐
really rich
and really creamy.
It's like mayonnaise gone wild.
Okay.
A little bit of red beni shoga,
which is pickled ginger.
‐Beautiful.
‐Some scallions.
Is that bonito flakes
we're getting ready to go for?
‐We are.
‐You're an animal.
And some nori.
Can't ignori that.
You can not.
Here we go.
That is one of the most
unique dishes
I've ever tried
in a food truck.
That has got such
a gourmet flair to it.
One minute, it's all pork.
Next minute,
it's all veggie and creamy.
Then it's the sour coming
from the pickled ginger.
Then you're over
into the crunchiness,
the texture on the outside
of the pancake.
Then you got the creaminess
of the inside of the pancake.
Oh, dude, it's so good.
Okonomiyakis ‐‐
tickets 1 and 2.
It's hard to describe, but it's
such a unique experience.
Beautiful sauce on top.
It's just a really tasty dish.
They can always get this?
‐No.
‐No?
Well, that's good.
‐[ Chuckles ]
Because we change
our menu so often.
If they want to find
where you're at
and what you're serving,
they go online.
Yep.
It's always changing.
FIERI: 'Cause everything depends
on what he's picking out
fresh at the farms.
He even has a board on his truck
that shows what came from where.
Plating up
some braise octopus.
He gives so much back
to the community.
MAN: All the tips usually go
to a local charity.
Every week he picks
a different charity.
Ticket number 3 ‐‐
crispy calamari salad.
‐Got any other "wow" factors?
‐We do.
All right, when we come back,
Chef Kyle,
well, he's gonna serve up
another amazing dish.
Laphet thock salad
with braised octopus.
He uses Pohole ferns.
Pohole is like
a fiddlehead fern.
With poached octopus.
Legit?
See you in a bit.
♪♪♪
So welcome back.
Hanging out with Chef Kyle,
the true farm‐to‐table guy,
at Maui Fresh Streatery.
We're at just some
random parking lot.
You know the idea
on food trucks.
FIERI:
But you can research where
he's at and what he's serving,
which is smart since the dude
doesn't stick to one menu.
Spicy tuna poke bowl.
Every week is always
something different.
WOMAN:
He uses all local ingredients,
and he nails the flavors
every single time.
Next up,
what are we doing?
Pohole fern, laphet thock salad,
with braised octopus.
Didn't The Beatles
have a song with that?
Uh, I don't know.
I like everything
about this dish.
The flavor and the texture
is so amazing and so unique.
Let's get started.
‐Hawaiian octopus.
‐Okay.
First we're gonna clean it,
so a little Hawaiian sea salt.
That just takes off the slime.
‐Got it.
Just give them a rinse
with some fresh water.
How long
we gonna simmer?
One hour with one
can of local beer.
‐Really?
‐Yes.
All right, Chef,
fiddlehead ferns.
Hawaiian fiddlehead ferns.
We've got some nice,
salted boiling water.
And they cook really quickly.
‐Then to an ice bath.
Right into an ice bath.
And they're ready to go.
The octopus is cooled.
Add that right into
our mixing bowl.
And this is called limu kohu,
local seaweed.
A little sesame oil.
And give that a quick stir.
‐Okay.
So we're gonna go ahead
and build our salad now.
Our blanched and shocked Pohole
ferns, Hawaiian fiddleheads,
some local Kula onions,
which is a sweet onion.
‐Okay.
‐Some cherry tomatoes,
toasted sesame seeds,
a little chopped,
roasted macadamia nuts.
This is what we call inamona,
a roasted candlenut.
The old candlenut.
A little bit
of fried garlic.
It's a food truck, sir.
It's not a space shuttle.
We're almost ready
for takeoff.
Dried, chopped shrimp,
toasted coconut,
our marinated octopus,
our vinaigrette,
which is roasted
garlic oil,
fresh lime juice,
and fish sauce.
And finally some
fresh jalapeños.
‐And that's all she wrote?
‐Mixy, mixy, stirry, stirry.
All those textures
and those flavors ‐‐
you want to really
blend that together.
Where are the bowls?
[ Chuckles ]
I like your style.
Look at that.
That's how you get it done,
ladies and gentlemen.
[ Chuckles ]
Bro,
it's ridiculously good.
‐Thank you.
‐Just like a symphony of flavor.
♪♪♪
Probably the most tender
octopus I've had in Maui.
The fiddleheads
are cooked perfectly.
There's still crunch
to them,
but you get all
the flavor of them.
It's just the whole thing,
dude.
It's coming together.
I am blown away.
Order ready for Tracy ‐‐
Pohole fern, laphet thock salad.
It's prepared to perfection.
Extremely satisfying
to the palate.
So, when "Triple D"
rolls to Maui,
the crew brings their wives.
So, this is Donnie's wife
and this is Jeff's wife.
Donnie. Jeff.
What do you think?
Really good fern
and really good, tender octopus.
He obviously has a passion,
and it comes through
in the food.
KAWAKAMI:
Order of kamikaze fries.
I'll try anything on his menu,
'cause it's just that great.
I'm in awe, bro.
You're such a talented chef
with such a phenomenal
imagination.
It's overwhelming
just how cool you are.
Thank you.
‐Thank you.
Come meet this cat.
Oh, and the food's great, too.
FIERI:
Up next, a Mexican marketplace
in Norfolk...
This place is legit,
man.
...busting
out the family cookbook...
When you taste this,
you are gonna shovel this.
...that runs deep
into the homeland.
I've never had
Mexican lamb soup.
I've never even heard
of Mexican lamb soup.
♪♪♪
So I'm here
in Norfolk, Virginia.
And I'm right across
the street ‐‐
Well, you can't see it.
That's Chesapeake Bay.
And down that way, uh,
three miles ‐‐ Virginia Beach.
So, I couldn't be eating
further away from Mexico.
So what kind of food
am I here to try?
Naturally, Mexican food.
And not just any Mexican food.
We're talking some
regionally‐authentic Mexican.
This is Jessy's
Tienda y Taqueria.
♪♪♪
We got some al pastor tacos
heating up over here.
This is original,
this is authentic,
and this is the real deal.
‐Quantos chile rellenos.
‐Order up.
MAN:
I'm originally from Mexico.
You can't really find
any of this type of food
anywhere in the Norfolk area.
FIERI: This one‐of‐a‐kind
market/restaurant
is a labor of love dished out
by the Romero siblings.
That's a family recipe.
It's from my dad.
‐Like real‐deal family recipes?
‐Yes.
My dad is from
Hidalgo, Mexico.
It's a little northwest
of Mexico City.
FIERI:
And while this place is named
after sister Jessy,
she's working right alongside
her brothers, Victor and Jorge,
keeping everything running
and those
regional recipes coming.
Order up ‐‐ consommé,
corn tacos!
I really love
this lamb consommé.
I get it
every time I come.
My first time trying it,
that was it.
I just wanted it from then on.
FIERI: I've never had
Mexican lamb soup.
I've never even heard
of Mexican lamb soup.
This is from the central
part of Mexico.
It comes with soup
and three tacos.
‐Lamb tacos?
‐Lamb tacos.
Give me the rundown.
Let's see it.
Garbanzo beans,
some white rice,
chile morita,
directly from Mexico.
‐Okay.
‐Avocado leaves.
Half an onion
and a full garlic head.
This is what gives
flavor to the soup.
Put this in the bottom
of the pot,
put the steamer
right above it.
Okay.
This is the basis
of the soup.
This is gonna
overflow the bowl.
And we're gonna use that
to steam the lamb.
Correct.
To steam the lamb.
Cover it all up
with banana leaves.
All right.
‐Chunks of lamb.
‐Yep.
We're spread a little
salt around it.
Some more onions so that
this sweats down onto the meat.
Run the heat four hours.
I've been dying
to do this.
[ Chuckles ]
All right, meat comes out,
we're gonna shred that.
Yep. So we'll start off
with a taco.
We got three.
Now, remember the garbanzo
beans and the rice?
Yes, yes, yes.
At the bottom.
Here we go.
And here's the consommé
de borrego.
Onions, some extra cilantro
for the soup, and voilà.
Mmm.
When you taste this,
you are gonna shovel this.
Everything you love
about a great...
rissole, just got deeper
and richer with the lamb.
You're making me hungry, man.
Can I dig in?
Aw, man.
Come on.
I'm serious. I can't get it
in there fast enough.
Lamb has that distinct
flavor and that depth.
And this is so simple
with those banana leaves
and the little bit
of the garlic,
a little bit of the lime.
And the fact that
you're taking the meat,
utilizing that
into the taco.
One of my new
favorite Mexican dishes.
‐Thank you.
‐Consommé and tacos.
MAN: It's got a little bit
of spice to it.
The rice and the garbanzo
beans are phenomenal.
MAN #2: The lamb ‐‐
absolutely delicious.
Tender, well‐seasoned.
Two more huaraches, please.
You don't expect to have
this wonderful restaurant
connected to a grocery store.
Just between you and I,
how many times have you bought
one of the Mexican
wrestling masks?
Only three.
Only three times.
ROMERO: My dad opened it.
It was the convenience.
and then, when I came over,
he said, "All right,
let's add the bakery,
let's add a butcher shop."
FIERI: Which has led to
the full‐on restaurant.
Huarache a la Mexicana.
The most authentic thing
on the menu are the huaraches.
They start with fresh masa.
It's steak, beans all together.
It's awesome.
We're gonna be doing
huarache a la Mexicana.
‐Huarache?
‐Una chancla.
A la chancla.
It's like an oblong tortilla
with the masa on the outside
and a little bit
of the beans on the inside.
It is a specialty.
So we're gonna make
some pinto beans
so that we can make
some refried beans
to stuff
the huarache with.
‐Okay.
‐Water.
Some salt here.
Half an onion.
Oil.
This'll go for an hour
to an hour and 30 minutes,
till they're nice and tender.
So we're just gonna
scoop them out, refry them.
And this is the middle
of the huaraches?
‐Yep.
‐Next, what's up?
We're gonna be doing
some arrachera steaks.
‐Arrachera.
‐Inside skirt.
We use a combination of garlic,
cumin, black pepper,
bitter orange adobo.
We mix this real good and we
sprinkle it through the steak.
And then tenderize.
Let them marinate for a good
at least 12 hours.
Beautiful.
All right, we're gonna
start making some masa.
So we got corn flour,
water, and some flour.
Just beat this until
all the water is gone.
Roll it up,
punch a hole into it
to put in a nice spoonful
of refried beans.
Roll it into
a little burrito,
and then we just start
squeezing the masa out.
And the idea is not
to have the beans come
outside of the masa.
Correct. And we got
a huarache ready to cook.
Crisp up both sides?
‐Yep.
‐Steak on the flattop.
Cheese on top
of the huarache.
So melted cheese.
What cheese is on there?
Queso oaxaca.
We top it with the skirt steak,
and then it gets a cactus,
Jalapeño,
sweet onion bulbs.
‐And that's it?
‐That's it.
As soon as I get
a handmade tortilla,
and I get that
little caramelization
that happens
on that tortilla,
then I'm right in Mexico.
The nopale's what makes it...
‐Yeah.
‐...in my opinion.
‐That cactus.
The melted oaxaca cheese
on top of it is dynamite.
Fantastic.
‐Thank you, man.
I mean, I'm like not
joking around, like fantastic.
Pork and 2 minutes
on the huarache.
The steak is perfectly seasoned.
Good stuff.
It's something
you definitely have to try
when you come out here.
Because anybody can make tacos,
but not anybody can make this.
All right, I've got
the flour tortillas going.
I've tried food from all sorts
of places around the world,
and Jessy's is one
of my favorites.
Definitely more than
chips and salsa.
You got to come
meet this guy.
The whole family.
The place is legit, man.
Real deal.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
FIERI: Coming up, a unique spot
in Los Angeles...
I like
the way you roll.
...where it's
all about the bomb bowls...
This is all kinds
of funkin' flavor.
...and all kinds
of unexpected.
You've got
a real serious issue
of taking something
completely normal
and artifying it
into another dimension.
Where were you with that?
You were supposed to be
running the bass on that.
[ Both imitating guitar music ]
[ Laughs ]
♪♪♪
So I'm here on the Eastside
of Los Angeles
in an area known
as the Arts District
to check out a joint
where a 20‐year restaurant vet
has opened up her own gig.
Now, she's taken her
Asian influence,
the fact that she loved
to eat out of bowls,
and all this artistic energy,
put it together
in a breakfast,
lunch, and dinner place,
this is ediBOL.
♪♪♪
Hash is almost up.
The food here is incredible.
When you try something, it's
your favorite thing every time.
WOMAN: Like the BOLina.
ediBOL is such
a unique restaurant.
It's one of
the oddest names
I've ever seen in the hi‐‐
‐edi‐BOL.
‐Oh, I got that.
‐[ Chuckles ]
UYEDA: Every single thing
I design to be in a bowl.
FIERI:
Inspired by the meals owner
Andrea Uyeda learned to make
with her Japanese mother
and grandmother.
For like a year,
I just cooked at home
and came up
with different bowls.
The flavors just keep coming.
MAN: Roasted garlic
and herb pork hash.
The pork hash is a little salty,
a little sweet.
She's hit it out of the park
with this one.
All right, so give me
the breakdown.
‐Okay.
‐Pork butt that's been cubed.
Then we put salt...
Fresh‐cracked black pepper ‐‐
I'm impressed.
Yes.
Yellow onions.
Whole garlic cloves.
Thyme.
Rosemary.
And bay leaf.
‐Bay leaf.
And then?
Take your favorite beer
and then ‐‐
And copious amounts of oil.
Yes.
It's like a confit.
Marinate it
at least 24 hours.
Roast it in the oven
at 350 degrees.
For 4 1/2 hours.
Bring it out,
let it cool.
We're gonna shred it.
‐Very tasty.
‐Tender.
Scallions.
Red onion.
Chopped‐up capers.
Rosemary.
Parsley.
Fresh‐grated lemon zest.
‐Okay.
‐Lemon juice.
‐So this gets all mixed up.
‐Yes.
And what is the jus
we have here?
This is the renderings
from when we cooked it.
Then we put this
in the fridge,
and then we put it
on the griddle
and serve it up
with our biscuits.
Are we making
the biscuits?
‐Yes.
‐Of course we are.
We have sifted,
all‐purpose flour.
And then what we're gonna do
is sift baking powder,
baking soda,
salt, and sugar.
This is actually frozen,
grated butter.
Makes it light and airy.
‐I got you.
Sharp cheddar cheese.
‐Ouch. Sure is.
‐[ Chuckles ]
Scallions mixed in there.
Buttermilk and heavy cream.
Mix this all up and ‐‐
Then we put them on a sheet
tray, put them in the oven,
350 degrees for 8 minutes.
‐I like the way you roll.
‐Let's get cooking.
Butter, pork hash.
That's roasted butternut squash.
‐Got it.
All right, so we're gonna
crisp it up on both sides.
I put the biscuit on a sizzle
plate so it's nice and crusty.
You are so nice.
And let's get
this hash off.
The biscuit on there.
Your pickled golden raisins,
pickled onions, spiced,
caramelized almonds,
parsley,
tomatillo‐pineapple crema.
Tomatillo‐pineapple crema.
And then
our crispy poached egg.
You've got
a real serious issue
of taking something
completely normal
and artifying it into
another dimension.
This is all kinds
of funkin' flavor.
The key to the hash is all the
little accoutrements on there.
The pickled onions.
I love the almonds ‐‐ the little
crunch, that little bite.
And the pickled raisins ‐‐
I'm using that one.
And then you go over to this
little, light, flaky biscuit.
It's half biscuit,
half scallion pancake.
It's dynamite.
The pork hash has so many layers
that all come together
in such a lovely way.
The cheddar biscuit
will change your life.
The meals here at ediBOL
are visually stunning.
FIERI: And so is the decor,
which Andrea also designed.
WOMAN:
That's why I like coming here,
'cause every little component
is so thought through.
WOMAN #2: I find ediBOL not just
any kind of restaurant.
It's a lot of different tastes
and fusions from all over.
Miso peanut ramen.
The miso ramen is a really good
take on a traditional salad.
It's light and refreshing
with a lot of zest to it.
Talk to me, sister.
This is the dressing
for the miso peanut ramen.
Miso paste, honey, sesame oil,
canola oil, tamari,
rice wine vinegar,
garlic, ginger.
Blend this all up.
That'll be terrible.
I'll have two quarts of it.
‐[ Laughs ]
‐Mmm.
Next up?
‐Put it all together.
Every single ingredient,
I want to eat
the whole bowl
of it by itself.
Together,
I'm gonna lose myself.
And with that dressing...
All right!
Ramen noodles,
red peppers,
pickled shiitake mushrooms.
‐Got it.
‐Edamame.
‐Oh, I love Eddie's mommy.
Edamame ‐‐ I'll put more
in there for you.
‐There you go.
‐Pickled carrots.
Yes.
Love those, too.
‐Scallions.
‐Oh, yes.
Salt, pepper,
and miso dressing.
Green beans.
‐Chopped peanuts.
‐Lots of chopped peanuts.
It smells as good as you're
thinking it is right now.
[ Laughs ]
Chopped romaine.
And we put it
on the plate,
and toasted sesame seeds
on the top.
As you should.
There we go.
‐There we go.
‐Okay.
So just no hands, right?
‐[ Chuckles ]
I apologize for not
speaking right now.
I'm really
just trying to shovel
as much of this in my mouth
as I can.
You got any bigger forks?
The meatiness
of these mushrooms,
and you get that edamame,
and you get the beans
and then you get
the chew of the noodle,
with a really
righteous dressing.
I got to sound like a horse
eating that, don't I?
[ Imitates horse chomping ]
It is really
a complete meal.
You would be
super successful
if that was
the only thing you sold.
[ Chuckles ]
A very eclectic dish.
‐A good friend of mine,
Adam Housley,
big‐shot news reporter.
How great is that dish?
It's got every flavor
in it.
I mean, it's got a little bit
of sweet, a little bit of spice,
and the colors
and the presentation
on top of it ‐‐
fantastic.
Honey citrus chicken.
These people hit the jackpot
with ediBOL moving in down here.
That is a happy food,
a very happy place.
You're a happy person.
‐Yeah.
I love doing what I'm doing.
Well, there's no question
about that.
‐Thank you.
‐I was hugging you
'cause I wanted to whisper,
"Make another bowl."
[ Laughs ]
So that's it for this trip.
But don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins &amp; Dives."
What's up, homey?
I got you
a little something.
‐What is this?
‐[ Speaks indistinctly ]
[ Laughter ]
Everybody's a comedian
around here.
Whoo!
I'm out.
"I'm out. I'm out."
He said, "I'm out."