Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
We're cruising
into college towns.
Losing my mind
a little bit.
To dig into some A‐plus grub.
This is what a college student
would die for.
We got champion Thai
in Boulder, Colorado.
I'm about ready to drown
in my drool.
A one‐of‐a‐kind barbecue spot
in Columbus, Ohio.
The hogasaurus patties
are almost ready.
Plus...
‐If it's funky, I'll find it.
I haven't come up
with what this one is yet.
A rockin' club amping up
way more than music.
So you thought why not take
pierogi to a funk bar?
Only on "Triple D," baby.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins &amp; Dives."
♪♪♪♪
Now, in the world
of "Triple D,"
there are two types
of "Triple D" fans.
"Triple D" fans that will go
try a lot of joints.
And then there are the hardcore
"Triple D" fans
that will go anywhere,
try anything,
no matter what
the place looks like.
I'm here in Columbus, Ohio,
to check out Pierogi Mountain,
here at Cafe Bourbon Street.
♪♪♪♪
You want to come in, you want
to feel a little grungy.
This is where I'd come.
Bourbon Street's the cultural
center of Columbus.
It's a hub for musicians,
it's the hub for artists.
It's "Cheers"
of the punk world.
Apple juniper sausage up.
FIERI: And while the crowd's
rocking club regulars,
chef Matt Majesky and his vegan
buddy Charles Green
are rolling out recipes
at Pierogi Mountain,
the venue's
one‐of‐a‐kind kitchen.
It has great food
all night long.
So you thought why not take
pierogi to a funk bar?
Yeah, why not?
And where did
the recipe come from?
It was my great‐grandma's
recipe.
She was from
Poland originally.
Eight of the nine pierogies
that are on the menu
are vegetarian or vegan.
That is huge.
Yeah,
we wanted to be inclusive.
We wanted something
for everybody.
That's what
a punk bar says is,
"Bring your pipe and cloak,
you're welcome!"
Only on "Triple D,"
baby.
If it works, man,
you know.
I love the pierogies.
They're all hand‐made.
FIERI:
From great‐grandma's classic...
Three‐potato cheddar.
The cheddar
and potato pierogies,
they are divine.
FIERI: To off the chain.
Misir wot pierogi up.
It's an Ethiopian dish,
has spicy lentil filling.
It's delicious.
We're making a vegan
flaxseed dough for the...
Misir wot pierogi.
We have a huge Ethiopian
population in Columbus.
Yeah, as I expected.
We're gonna take the flaxseed,
dump it in the water there,
then boil it
for about two minutes.
‐Can I see your tattoo?
‐Oh, it's "Gravy Master."
Dude, I've seen
a lot of food tattoos.
Never so much
the gravy bottle.
It's awesome, dude.
And then I have
to strain it.
We just want the gel.
It can be a messy process
sometimes.
I see, I see.
And that's gonna work
as our binder.
‐That is our egg replacer.
‐Well done, my friend.
Let's bake some dough.
All‐purpose flour,
flaxseed oil.
‐Ooh.
‐See it has egg consistency.
Instant mashed potato.
‐Of course.
It makes the dough
a little bit lighter.
Like, think kind
of gnocchi dough.
Water, baking powder.
Add a little salt.
Gonna mix it
for about five minutes.
I want a spaghetti
and meatball pierogi.
You know, I've done
a pepperoni pizza pierogi.
Now, then you just
took my idea.
That's fine, man!
And we're gonna stick it
in the refrigerator for, like,
at least 15 minutes
just to let it set up.
‐Start making the filling.
‐We got some boiled potatoes,
then we got
some al dente lentil.
Onion powder.
‐Okay.
‐Garlic powder.
‐Right.
Berbere spice.
Losing my mind
a little bit.
I like to keep it
interesting.
Kosher salt.
Olive oil.
We're gonna mix it,
not over‐mix it,
'cause you want to have all
your textures of your lentils.
Gonna let this
rest overnight.
We got
the misir wot done.
The biggest thing
that you gotta deal with
is rolling
this dough out.
Yeah.
These are the molds that we use.
So this is gonna make six.
I'm good at math.
We got the vegan dough
right here.
I'm gonna put that
in the flour.
I'm just gonna roll it out.
Gonna flour up
that a little bit,
and I want
to flour up the mold.
One side down.
We're gonna add
our fillings.
You get real
precise with it.
Well, you don't want air pockets
or anything like that.
You fill the cavity
better than a dentist.
So now we roll out a sheet,
lay it on top.
This pressure rolling across
here will cut it through.
‐Absolutely.
‐Got it.
Those are not dainty
pierogies.
We boil 'em.
How long do they take
in the water?
Gonna take
about three minutes.
And then we cool them.
Then they go
to the flat top?
Yep.
We brown them up a little bit.
Right.
Put a little water down
to steam them, then dome them.
Like dumpling madness.
Yeah.
That's our misir wot pierogi,
and all things come standard
with sour cream
for the vegan ones.
Use vegan sour cream.
‐Got it.
Now we need
our caramelized onions.
And we're ready to go.
Brother, it's outstanding.
The vegan dough has this
awesome tenderness to it,
like a really good pasta.
The lentil texture
is outstanding.
It's the berbere that takes it
over the top.
‐Yeah.
‐I like that unique flavor.
You're venturing
into a territory
that I don't think
I've really seen anybody touch.
They're fantastic.
‐Thank you.
‐You rocked it, man.
Killed it.
On the outside,
it's very crispy,
and then on the inside
is this soft texture.
The spices in it are just
a little bit more deep
and earthy than the other
pierogies, I'd say.
I'm at a quaint little punk bar
here in Columbus, Ohio,
and who would I find
sitting here?
My mom.
‐[ Laughs ]
Now, when you bring your mom,
you also run into your cousins.
You guys have all
not been here before?
You better not have said
you've been here before.
Don't tell my mom.
I mean, this is like real,
official pierogies?
This is very good.
Joyce is a great cook
herself.
It's like a potsticker, huh?
It's good.
I'm thinking like a polka's
about ready to break out here.
‐Yeah.
‐It's not polka.
[ Grunge music plays ]
So here's the deal.
We're hanging out in my
birthplace, Columbus, Ohio,
at the Cafe
at Bourbon Street.
Yep.
When we come back
another dish.
I hope it does
what this does.
Makes me happy.
‐[ Laughs ]
♪♪♪♪
Welcome back.
Hanging out
with the pierogi master
at the Pierogi Mountain,
in a funky little joint
called Cafe Bourbon Street.
Yep.
Happens to be a punk bar
in Columbus, Ohio.
Small Hungarian poutine.
MAN: If you're looking
for some good homemade
Eastern European food
in a unique venue,
this is the place to be.
WOMAN: Chicken paprikash.
Chicken paprikash on top
of dumplings,
and it's delicious.
Chicken paprikash.
It's your dad's dish.
‐Yeah.
Last time I saw
chicken paprikash,
I think was at Grinders
in Kansas City, Missouri.
That guy was a character.
What makes great
chicken paprikash?
Wide variety of spices,
fresh vegetables.
Start it off, man.
We got some butter.
Chopped carrots.
Celery, paprika,
and some smoked paprika.
Black pepper, garlic powder,
kosher salt, onion powder.
‐Okay.
‐Then I got ground up bay leaf.
Granulated chicken bullion.
‐There you go, baby!
We're just gonna stir it
for a little bit
until the butter
gets melted in there,
and we've kind of toasted up
the spices a little.
Ooh, I love the scratching
of the spoon on the bottom.
[ Laughs ]
Boneless,
skinless chicken thighs.
And water.
‐Now some gravy master.
So this is gonna cook
for about an hour.
Now,
is this pierogi dough.
Yeah, that's our leftover
pierogi dough.
Add a little bit of water
to the dough,
take out little pieces,
drop them in the boiling water.
Panful of dumplings.
Put a steam on them, too,
so they puff up.
‐Here, they puff up.
‐They puff up.
The pierogi master says
they puff up.
All right, now that we've had
this boiling for about an hour,
they just kind of shredded up
the chicken a little bit
in the pot.
Got it. You just drop
in the sour cream right here.
I add a flour and water slurry
until it gets thick enough.
When you're listening to
a punk band in a packed bar,
you could have yourself
some chicken paprikash
over some pierogi
dumplings.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Go, go, go!
Then we're gonna throw
a nice healthy ladle on top.
Get your pillow ready.
I just want to taste
that paprikash soup nectar.
Oh. Dude, wow.
It's awesome chicken
and dumplings
made Polish‐Hungarian
style.
Having that leftover
pierogi dough
is a perfect thing
to do with it.
Super creamy. Then you get
that kick of the paprika.
Chicken thigh is exactly
what you want.
That's outrageous.
‐Need a hug?
Dude, that's a hug
in a bowl right there.
This is what a college student
would die for.
Ridonculous.
Fantastic.
[ Laughs ]
The flavors are something
you wouldn't expect.
Giant dumplings, and it's just
big pieces of vegetables.
‐Paprikash?
‐Paprikash.
This is really good.
This is just
a different kind of experience
than you're gonna get anywhere
else considering bar food.
How do you feel when my mom
and my cousin come rolling in?
Everybody's welcome here?
‐Oh, yeah.
‐Oh, absolutely.
They're always welcome here.
I'm coming back
for some music.
MAN: This is the last place
I would expect
to find somewhere this good.
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
I haven't come up
with what this one is yet.
‐[ Laughs ]
‐Congratulations.
‐Thanks, man.
‐You're gonna love this guy.
See you down here,
5:00 they open.
FIERI: Up next,
we're sticking to Columbus.
Am I getting punk'd?
For a smoking hog haven.
That's gorgeous.
Going all out when it comes
to farm to table.
It's kind of crazy, but I sure
appreciate you being crazy.
♪♪♪♪
I'm here in Columbus, Ohio,
just a little bit north
of Ohio State University,
to check out a food truck.
Guess where it's at.
In a parking lot
of a bar ‐‐
Ace of Cups
is what it's called.
And this just isn't
any barbecue pit.
This dude's gotta do
a barbecue his own way,
and most importantly,
he's raised his own hogs.
This is Ray Ray's Hog Pit.
♪♪♪♪
Full slab dry rub.
It's the best barbecue in town,
hands down.
Brat burger
going on the grill.
Ray Ray's food truck,
it's an institution in Columbus.
MAN: A lot of the pork
that he's serving on his truck
he raises right on his own farm.
FIERI: By using his own pigs,
chef and owner James Anderson
has more control
over the taste of his 'cue.
They're not pen‐raised.
They're eating
what you're feeding them,
and that's the type of meat that
you're using for the barbecue.
Yeah. It's richer, creamier fat,
more marbling.
Can I get the brat burger?
The brat burger
is super juicy.
I love the flavors.
‐What are we making?
‐Mangalista brat burger.
FIERI: That's whole hog.
So you've not added
fat to that at all.
Whole hog, uh‐uh.
These Mangalistas
have five‐inch back fat.
Dude!
That's gorgeous.
‐We like it fatty.
First, we're gonna start with
salt, garlic, cayenne pepper.
All spice, ground ginger,
white pepper.
Margarine, nutmeg, mace.
Then we're gonna mix it
right in the pan.
Whole hog
I like to beat it up
a little bit,
try to get the fat
and the meat to kind of...
‐Stick together?
‐Stick together a little better.
Okay.
That is a big patty,
dude.
We don't want to have
somebody say that we didn't
have enough meat
on that sandwich.
That's embarrassing.
It's embarrassing.
Then I just put it
on the gas grill.
Cheese on top,
and that's it.
The hogasaurus patties
are almost ready.
‐That's a good name.
‐What are you doing next?
We're gonna make
the honey mustard sauce
for the top of the burger.
‐Okay.
We start with some mayo.
Honey mustard.
Salt and pepper.
Really went crazy
with that.
Raw apple cider vinegar.
Mix it all up.
‐Okay.
Now we're gonna make
a brat sandwich.
On a one to 10
of enthusiasm levels,
you normally operate
at a...
‐Five.
‐That pretty much ‐‐
‐This is my happy face.
‐We're out of control right now?
‐Yeah.
Five is the ceiling.
So the 10‐ounce
hog patty...
Pickles, Napa cabbage.
‐Okay.
‐Onion.
Honey mustard sauce.
You're gracious with that now,
don't you.
Yeah, it's like the dressing
for us, kind of like a coleslaw.
Potatoes with that
on the side.
It's basically potatoes,
cheese, sour cream.
Any particular way
you like to eat this?
‐Fast.
‐Okay, good.
What number am I running right
now, one to 10?
You're usually
about a 10.
[ Laughs ]
Running hot.
The fat, it's like it almost
basted the meat while it cooked.
Love the crunch.
I thought it was way
too much dressing,
but you're right,
it makes that instant slaw.
It's juicy, it's moist.
Thank you.
This tastes like someone
went to make mac &amp; cheese,
and then, "Oh, we don't have
any macaroni."
‐Throw some potatoes.
‐Throw potatoes in there.
But it was raising your own hogs
to make a patty,
it's kind of crazy.
But I sure appreciate you
being crazy.
Crazy on five?
Can I get a t‐shirt
that says that?
Ray Ray's ‐‐
crazy on five.
Five minutes
on the brat burger.
Every town
that I visit "Triple D,"
Jeff Ruby happens to open
a restaurant there.
He's getting ready
to open one here in Columbus,
and I figure we would see
what he thinks
about this pig patty
sandwich.
The flavor, the texture,
it's not dry ‐‐
it's delicious.
It's perfect.
WOMAN:
The cabbage and the onions,
it just gives a really
nice crunch and bite.
So you come to Ohio,
you know that you're gonna get
your cousins from all over
Ohio showing up.
This is my Aunt Polly,
you know my mom and dad,
my cousin Tonya,
my cousin Heidi, Ellis,
it's Ian,
and of course, Carol.
The pig patty sandwich,
you try it?
‐Fabulous.
‐Real hamburger, yeah.
No, it wasn't burger,
that was pork.
‐That's why I say, hamburger.
‐Pork burger.
A ham ‐‐ ham burger.
Ba dum dum.
Sorry I didn't get it.
All the food on Ray Ray's truck,
it never disappoints.
Where does the name Ray Ray
come from?
Ray is my middle name.
Ray Ray is my nickname.
It's a good barbecue name.
That is a great
barbecue name.
I didn't know what I was
gonna get when I drove up
and the dude's name
was Ray Ray.
I'm like,
this could go anywhere.
Some people call him Jamie,
some people call him James,
some people call him Ray Ray.
Call it delicious
is what it is.
Got a full rack
of St. Louis spare ribs.
Hot on the side.
You can't get a better rib
in Ohio.
MAN: They got the perfect
amount of bark.
It's got a little pull.
‐What else you gonna do?
‐St. Louis spare ribs here.
‐Okay. Salt, pepper?
‐Nothing.
These are going in the smoker
with nothing on them?
Nothing on them.
Am I getting punk'd?
You want to taste the pork
or do you want to taste
cumin and cinnamon?
I mean, at least salt
and pepper.
If I dry rub it now,
then it's already salty.
But if I put it on at the end,
I can go heavy,
then it's gonna
coat your lips.
Let's see it, buddy.
We're gonna put them
in the smoker for about
four and a half hours,
225.
All right, where we at?
We're gonna do
our house dry rub.
Okay.
Salt, garlic,
chili powder, sugar.
‐And the paprika.
‐That's the dry rub.
Next up, barbecue sauce.
‐Sugar.
‐Some of the dry rug we made.
Worcestershire sauce,
apple cider vinegar,
and white vinegar.
A tub of molasses.
‐Ketchup. Mix her up.
‐Okay.
So we're gonna
take these ribs off,
put them right
onto the grill.
We're just cook that rub
on a little bit.
And I'm gonna try
to burn that fat.
I like a little bit of black
crunchy fat on the bottom.
There's something about
hard char.
Nice fat.
Lots of juice,
dynamite dry rub.
For a guy that doesn't
dry rib at all,
you go generous
with the dry rib after.
That's my whole point.
That's why I don't put them
on early, I want to...
That's you're all smooth,
I got you.
Tasty, man.
Interest you
in some sauce?
I'll tell you what I do
really like the most
is the char
on that skin.
That's a really
good rib, man.
Half a slab dry,
half a slab wet.
The ribs are great.
They're big, they're juicy.
And I'm a picky rib eater
because I don't want
to fight to get my meat
off the bone.
‐Right.
‐Just comes right off.
I would probably half these
every day if I could.
Jerk chicken.
The best barbecue
on planet earth.
I don't think we've ever
heard that on "Triple D."
Best barbecue,
planet earth.
I'll say it's the best
in the solar system.
‐You're out.
‐He's got me beat.
Coming here, it's a privilege
to eat his food.
‐Well done.
‐Thank you.
‐Was that a five and a half?
‐Five and a half.
Let's get shots
and we'll get it up to six.
‐We're going to six!
‐[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up
in Boulder, Colorado...
I'd like everybody at home
to get prepared
for a food coma
in T‐minus 20 and counting.
A mother‐daughter team
going the extra mile.
We're not gonna do
anything easy, are we?
No.
To make their
Thai specialty sing.
It's not just
a drum solo here.
I mean, this is
the whole band rocking.
‐Oh, you want to follow me!
‐Aagh!
‐I don't know what that was.
‐Oh, that's my aunt.
I haven't seen her
in a while.
♪♪♪♪
[ Harp chord plays ]
I love coming
to college campus towns.
I'm here in Boulder, Colorado,
about a mile from the campus.
Now, why do I love it?
You got a lot of activities,
you got a lot of cool bars,
hear a lot of great music.
And the food ‐‐
the food's outrageous.
You got A. M. food,
you got pub grub,
you got late‐night,
and you got ethnic.
Why do you have ethnic?
Because you got people
from all over the world
who want food
from all over the world.
This is Aloy Thai.
♪♪♪♪
The best authentic Thai
that I've had here in Boulder.
Palm salad!
MAN: You can definitely feel
the preparation
and the love
that goes in each dish.
It's literally
my flavor temple.
FIERI: And the cooking goddesses
are Kim Naka
along with her daughters
Bo and Arisa.
This is as traditional
as I would find it
if I went to Bangkok?
‐Yes.
‐Where does the name come from?
Aloy mean delicious.
Delicious Thai?
Yes.
Yep.
Egg noodles are done.
When I get cravings
for curry or noodles,
I always come here.
‐Khao soi for you.
‐Thank you.
I have had the khao soi,
and it is amazing.
A wonderful,
creamy soup with a nice chunk
of meat right
in the middle.
So what are we
gonna make today?
‐It's called khao soi.
‐Khao soi, okay.
It's like
a curry noodle soup.
Where do you get
your noodles from?
‐California.
‐I just came from California.
I could have
brought you some.
So we got lemongrass.
Galangal, garlic.
Dried chilies that we steeped
in water.
‐Water, yeah.
‐Okay.
‐Turmeric.
‐Fried it ahead of time.
Ginger.
Fried the ginger
a little bit.
‐Onion.
‐Cilantro root.
‐Yeah.
‐Fried chili.
Shallots.
Shrimp paste.
Whoa!
[ Laughing ]
You know when you see
a boxing movie
and the guy gets knocked out
and they bring up that thing,
and they crack it
right there?
Shrimp paste.
Go, "Whoa!"
Cardamom, salt.
A little salt.
And this is just
the foundation of the...
Khao soi.
‐Khao soi?
‐Yeah.
So we're gonna fry up
the khao soi?
Yeah. Smell?
Oh, I can smell it.
I'm about ready to drown
in my drool.
Slowly add
the coconut cream.
Now we're gonna put it
in the pot.
Got it?
‐She's got it.
Look at the muscle.
And we turn on.
Now it's the coconut milk.
Fish sauce.
Palm sugar.
Is palm sugar the typical
type of sugar
that you use
in Thailand?
Yeah, just because
it's more aroma,
it's different taste.
Regular sugar.
Now what do we add
with the khao soi?
Chicken thighs.
Are we gonna cook the chicken
thigh a special way?
‐Yes, yeah.
‐Yeah.
Of course we are.
'Cause we're not gonna do
anything easy, are we?
We're not.
No, we're not gonna do
anything easy.
See that smile? "No, idiot,
we're doing anything easy."
Star anise and cinnamon.
‐Peppercorn.
The key is really toasting
the spices, waking them up.
The chicken.
So this is gonna cook here
for how long?
15 minutes.
Next, cilantro root
and the celery.
Garlic, palm sugar.
Soy sauce, salt.
So now we add the chicken
to that.
‐Yes.
‐And how long's it cook?
Two hours.
We take the noodles
that are made in California.
‐Mm‐hmm.
‐Just a little bit of noodles.
'Cause you got
the fried noodles, too.
I'd like everybody at home
to get prepared
for a food coma
in T‐minus 20 and counting.
Between the coconut milk
and the curry
with fried on top of it.
Red onion and green onion.
Dried chili pepper
and then the pickled cabbage.
Pickled cabbage.
Now I'm doing it like
I should be doing it in...
Yes, I Thailand, yep.
So I'm in Thailand now.
So only speak to me in Thai.
‐[ Speaking Thai ]
‐Yeah, yeah. See?
Ahoy, mate.
I understood that.
Wow. The beauty of the dish
is that it's so simple.
Yet when you use
great ingredients,
the depth of the flavor
is outstanding.
[ Muffled ] I mean,
what I really mean is
I can't shovel it
in my face fast enough.
Delicious. Aloy.
‐Aloy.
Crispy noodles, and you stick
them into the broth.
It's perfect.
Got the nice curry
with the good kick to it,
and the meat
is just really delicious.
Where did you learn
to cook?
Cooking for my family
when they're young.
She cooked for her 11 sisters
and brothers.
10, 10.
Well, 10, 'cause you're one
of the 11.
‐Yeah.
The food has that deep
comforting feel
that you expect when you eat
at someone's house.
Lamb and curry chicken.
I had the lemongrass chicken,
and it is amazing flavors.
It's marinated
for a really long time,
so it's really packing
all those spices.
What are we making next?
The lemongrass
chicken barbecue.
‐Lemongrass chicken barbecue?
‐Yes.
Tamarind sauce.
Thai thin soy sauce.
Here at the soy sauce
tasting center.
Oyster sauce, pepper.
‐White pepper.
‐Black pepper, sugar.
Lemongrass.
‐Okay.
‐Lime leaf.
‐Sri Lanka lime leaf.
Oh, fantastic.
Cilantro root
and the turmeric.
And then we add
the chicken in,
and they make
chicken milkshakes.
[ Laughs ]
‐Pour it on the chicken.
‐Yes.
How long is it
gonna marinate?
‐Overnight.
‐And we grill it.
We have the grilled
chicken.
Tamarind sauce.
So how do we make
the tamarind sauce?
Tamarind, sugar,
and then fish sauce.
Ground rice.
‐Ground rice?
You like spicy or no?
I love spicy.
Cilantro.
♪♪♪♪
That's thigh,
but it eats as tender
as perfectly‐cooked
chicken breast.
I mean, it's great
the way it is,
but the tamarind sauce...
‐Mm‐hmm.
‐Yes.
With the sweet, sour,
and heat of the lemon chicken,
then the gritty crunch
of the dried rice,
when you put it all together,
it becomes outrageous.
It's not just
a drum solo here.
I mean, this is
the whole band rockin'.
Lemongrass barbecue chicken.
The sauce is amazing.
There's a whole kick
of different flavors.
WOMAN: The chicken
is really nice and tender ‐‐
one of my favorite
dishes here.
I've been eating my way through
the menu for a few years.
That's a good thing
to do.
You're gonna have a hobby,
that's my hobby.
Yes.
I come back time
and time again
because the food's
always gonna be good.
A mile away, there's a bunch
of college students going,
"I never knew
about that place!"
They're gonna know now.
‐Thank you.
‐Nice job.
That's it for this week.
But don't you worry,
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country!
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive‐ins &amp; Dives."
It looked like you poured it
right out of your tattoo.
Look at that, just strains it
right from the tat!
[ Laughter ]