Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, whoa, whoa!
...we're cruising the country...
Oi!
...for a passport of flavor...
[ Muffled ] Could I shovel that
in my face any faster?
...like at an old-school
Mexican bakery in San Antonio...
I'm impressed.
...and in Lansing, Michigan...
This is your jam,
right here.
...a Middle Eastern joint
keeping it real...
"Shower-ma"?
Shawarma.
...and an Asian 'cue combo
where you'd least
expect to find it.
Whoa!
Look at him go!
There ya go.
[ Chuckles ] Hey!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives."
♪♪
Well, I'm here on the west side
of Lansing, Michigan,
in the middle
of the solar eclipse.
And I'm here
to check out a joint
that's serving up some
amazing Mediterranean food.
Which way is the place,
because I heard it's the bomb?
This is Zaytoon.
♪♪
RASHED: Beef Kabob
You can always expect
a plate of flavor.
Hummus appetizer,
Greek salad up, guys.
This is Samy's passion.
If it's not authentic,
it wouldn't be Samy.
FIERI: That's 'cause
after 20 years in the biz,
Michigan native Samy Rashed
brings a family tree
full of street cred
to his Middle Eastern menu.
My mom is
a phenomenal cook.
Where's your mom from?
Syria.
Where's your dad from?
Palestine.
This is in your DNA.
This is your comfort food.
It is.
I need lamb chops,
medium-well.
WOMAN: You could eat here
every day of the week,
and you're never eating
the same flavor.
SERVER:
Chicken shawarma and rice.
The chicken shawarma is
one of their staples.
You can just taste
all of the seasonings.
It's so good.
Chicken shawarma.
Is that how you do it?
The word "shower."
Shower.
"Ma" -M-A.
Shower-ma?
There you go!
Shawarma.
All right.
What are we making first?
Marinade for
the chicken shawarma.
What is this -- sumac?
What do we got?
Sumac.
[ Laughs ] Point!
Good call.
[ Vocalizing ]
Very nicely done.
You know where I learned
about sumac?
Aarti Sequeira,
the phenomenal chef.
Sumac, having that nice
little lemony flavor to it,
is so awesome.
Aarti,
big shout-out, girl.
You got your tomato paste,
the garlic, dried sumac,
crushed red pepper,
ground black pepper.
I got Spanish paprika...
Okay.
ground cumin,
ground coriander.
That's one of those flavors that
starts to surprise people.
Regular salt,
oregano,
some white
distilled vinegar.
You add some water.
Whisk it all together.
Ah, see?
Nice, ain't it?
Pour this on
our chicken thighs.
This is going to marinate
for how long?
-24 hours.
-Bring it out.
-Yep, fillet them open.
-Got it.
So, you got your
vertical broiler here.
Push down as hard
as you can,
and as you get up
to about halfway, I shave it.
This is your jam right here.
Every morning.
-Onion on top?
-Yep.
How long does it have
to cook on the spit
before it's ready
for service?
25 minutes to 1/2 hour.
So, you are just
getting all the...
Yumminess.
I want to reach in there,
but I'll lose a finger.
On the plate, you got
some of my spicy hummus,
Lebanese rice
with vermicelli in it,
shaved chicken,
and my garlic sauce.
This is made
from cooked potatoes,
heavy-duty mayonnaise,
fresh garlic cloves,
salt, lemon salt...
[ Whirring ]
...and ice.
♪♪
Do people stack it up,
build it up?
Me, I mix it all
together.
♪♪
Wow, that's good, bro.
Nice.
Really simple,
done exactly right --
tender,
it's flavorful,
but the real kicker is
that garlic sauce.
I have a real good buddy
of mine named Mikey Z,
makes the best barbecue,
probably, out of anybody I know.
There's a lot of similarities
going on here.
Ironically enough,
Mikey Z. just lives right down
the road here,
in Detroit.
Mikey: Hey, Guy, what up?
Are you close by?
I'm right in
your neighborhood.
Come here, try this.
Tell me what you think.
There we go.
[ Laughing ]
Do the hunch?
I didn't say
you're getting ready to fly.
Mmm, that's really
good chicken.
Good texture --
It's not falling apart.
it's not dried out.
So anyhow, I t--
Whoa, whoa.
♪♪
Chicken shawarma combo
in the window.
You get the grilled taste
of the shawarma.
I like the flavor,
the seasonings.
It's excellent.
It's fabulous.
You have an eclectic mix
of great food in Michigan.
I don't think people
know that.
Detroit's got the biggest
Arabic population
in the United States.
RASHED: Hummus lamb ready
in three minutes, please.
FIERI: How would you
describe this to somebody?
I feel like I'm eating
healthy, fresh.
This is Patty and Jim,
the mother and father
of Nate Dogg,
who is one of our
favorite camera guys
here on "Triple D"
and on "Triple G."
I see you're having
the stuffed grape leaves.
Have you ever
had those before?
Yes, I have.
And it's a real treat
to have them,
because it's a hard thing
for me to make myself.
The lamb grape leaves
are my favorite --
so good.
Lamb grape leaves.
Lamb, beef, stuffed.
Lamb, beef?
Lamby-lamby, beef-beef.
I'm going to mix
the filling.
I got my long-grain
white rice.
Tomato paste.
Ground coriander,
some salt.
Black pepper.
Allspice.
some of my famous
lemon salt,
minced garlic,
some olive oil.
So, you're bringing in
the leg of lamb,
and you're bringing in
the chuck roll,
cutting it,
grinding it yourself.
Grinding it myself.
This is a better ratio
of meat to rice
than I see in a lot
of grape leaves.
People cut corners.
I don't.
Now, we get the leaves,
start stuffing?
That's it.
They come in fresh in brine.
Fill it up, roll it up.
And how are
we gonna cook them?
Got a stock pot here.
Add two of those tomatoes
for me, please.
♪♪
Two of those bowls of tomatoes,
please.
Just gotta be precise.
And then, I'll stack them all,
keep on going around.
How many will this hold?
About 300.
How do you
get these done?
I have a young lady
who is actually a machine.
I'm here!
[ Both laugh ]
This is the machine?
This is my machine.
300 in an hour --
Let me see it.
So she has a little press
and pull that
she does right there,
rolls them up.
Yeah.
All right,
300 in one hour.
I'll be back.
♪♪
All right, so we've got
the homemade hummus.
Put a little bit
of tabbouleh in there.
This is made
from scratch.
I actually use quinoa
instead of wheat.
It's so fresh,
so light.
Got to put the olive,
some peppers there.
And you got your
grape leaves.
Good to rock.
♪♪
Delicious.
It's the right amount
of grape leaf
to the mixture,
and the right amount
of meat to rice.
It's fresh.
It's flavorful.
It's light.
This is that same level
of the shawarma.
It's legit --
I mean, super legit.
Lamb grape appetizer
coming out!
It's just mouthwatering.
The grape leaves are
very tender.
The hummus is really good.
It's nice and creamy.
It's always good stuff --
always good.
There you go, folks.
Meet the man, try the food.
You'll love
the experience.
Well done.
Thanks, bro.
FIERI: Up next, a Mexican bakery
in San Antonio...
You so know I want
one of these.
...serving up a melt-
in-your-mouth creation...
It's really luxurious.
...I just knew the boys would
dive right into.
I gotta do all
the work.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in San Antonio, Texas,
just down the street
from the Alamo,
and we all know, there's
no basement in the Alamo.
Anyhow, I'm here
to check out a bakery --
not just any bakery,
but a Mexican bakery.
and not just any Mexican bakery.
a Mexican bakery run
by two brothers
and got an incredible story.
This is La Panaderia.
♪♪
Carlos, we need to put this
in the oven in 20 minutes.
It's bread culture that
you can't find anywhere else
in San Antonio.
SERVER: Mexican Cubana.
I grew up in Mexico City,
and this place
reminds me of that.
FIERI: Because
Jose and David Caceres
grew up there, too,
where for them,
bread making
was a family affair.
My mom taught us
the art of baking.
And what a classroom.
Their mom ended up going from
a small street-side operation
to distributing baked goods
to stores all around Mexico.
She was
a businesswoman.
Eventually, the brothers
went out on their own
and opened this shop
in the States,
with Jose running things
and David diving right
in to the golden era
of Mexican baking.
We're trying to recreate
Mexico from the 1950s.
So now you're getting
the artisan side back in.
Yeah, exactly.
So, how many different
types of pastries
do you guys make?
15 to 20.
And how many different
types of bread?
Five to six types
of breads.
FIERI: Which range from using
ancient grains to creating
a south-of-the-border/
San-Francisco-type mash-up.
This is the telera,
and this is birote.
It's a Mexican
sourdough.
It has that homemade feel.
Okay, Chef,
give me the rundown.
We have everything ready
to make the sourdough.
So, this is
the starter?
How long has this
been running?
20 years.
20 years?
My brother always says
that it is my baby.
It is your baby!
So, we want to activate
the starter a little bit.
Pour a little water.
Got it.
Now, the starter.
Yeah, exactly.
The flour.
Yeast?
Malt.
And a little salt.
And how long
is this going to mix?
First speed,
five minutes,
and second speed,
nine minutes.
So, we have it on the spin cycle
right now. We'll come back.
We're doing delicates
at the moment.
[ Laughing ]
Then what do we do
with it?
We put it in
the proofing containers.
Okay.
And the magic is
gonna happen in the folds.
We let it proof.
After that, what happens?
We cut it, we weigh it,
and we shape it.
Rest it one more day.
And what temperature are we
gonna cook these at?
476 degrees Fahrenheit.
Not 475.
Exactly.
This oven is
very sophisticated,
and it allows you to bake
with that precision.
I'm impressed.
All right, brother.
Let's do it.
♪♪
You so know
I want one of these.
Oh, whoa, whoa!
We know it's ready.
Look at the steam
coming out of it.
[ Chuckles ]
Is it good?
[ Muffled ]
It's fantastic.
It's got better texture
and depth of flavor
than I've had
in Mexican bread before.
Thank you.
Could I shovel that in my face
any faster?
[ Laughing ]
[ Normal voice ] Now, people can
come in and just buy bread,
or they can also have it made
as a sandwich, right?
Yeah, exactly.
My favorite is
the chicken milanesa sandwich.
WOMAN: Beautifully-
cooked chicken,
that nice crusty bread
on the outside.
WOMAN #2: It's creamy
with the avocado,
and it's spicy with
the pickled jalapenos.
All right, give me
the game plan, buddy.
So, we have the chicken
here with this egg.
And where are the breadcrumbs
coming from?
[ Laughing ]
So, now it's ready to go.
All right, Chef,
that's my roll of choice.
Are you gonna canoe it?
Yeah.
Guacamole, cilantro mayo.
We have the chicken
milanesa here.
Then, I put the jalapenos,
the cheese.
Swiss.
Then, it's ready
to go into the oven.
What is this?
Those are the beans.
They're very,
very authentic.
We bake them
with cilantro.
We make them
in the traditional way.
♪♪
Those are good beans.
The sandwich should
be ready now.
It's ready to eat.
♪♪
Mmm.
[ Muffled ]
It's a really good sandwich.
♪♪
The bread's really fantastic.
It's that awesome crust.
Yeah, exactly.
Little touch of the jalapeno.
[ Normal voice ]
Swiss I thought was funny,
but it fits.
You're getting
a scratch-made sandwich
right down here,
in the middle
of the tourist area
of San Antonio.
You're getting a deal.
♪♪
SERVER: Chicken milanesa.
It's one of those sandwiches
that you can eat everyday.
If I was the mayor
of Flavortown,
this would be
the official sandwich.
Did he just pull out
"mayor of Flavortown"?
[ Laughter ]
These guys are with
Pararescue and Combat Control.
Hunter and I hung out
with these three cats
in probably one of the most
amazing experiences
I've ever had
in my life,
and that was that we jumped
out of a plane at...
13,000 feet.
You guys keep up
all the hard work and be safe.
And watch out for
all the sweets, okay, Ron?
All right.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: But that's definitely
hard to do here.
WOMAN: They have lots
of lovely pastries.
And you grab a tray and tongs,
so you can just
hand-select them yourself
as you walk through the line.
I can understand why
you have lines waiting.
And I'm gonna keep you waiting,
'cause when we come back,
I'm going to bring
two croissant aficionados
to come make
the next dish.
Cool?
Okay.
SERVER: Tequila
almond croissants.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're here
in San Antonio, Texas,
at La Panaderia --
a Mexican bakery,
where David Caceres
gets inspiration
from his home country
and from around the globe.
Because my mom taught us
to travel around the world,
we have influence
from a lot of cultures --
from Italy, from France,
from Spain.
David is an amazing baker.
And everything here is
super-authentic.
FIERI: Or an original,
like a classic French pastry
with a unique Mexican twist.
The Tequila almond croissant
is just magnetic.
WOMAN: It's so, like, ooey-gooey
with this almond-tequila mix
in the middle and spread on top.
Doing a real croissant --
and you did this
when we were in France --
is a true art form.
And I had to bring in
the official croissant tester,
Rider.
So, Chef David,
what are we doing?
Okay, we're going to make
the paste
for the tequila-
almond croissant.
So, this is just
the spread
that's going inside
of the croissant?
Yes.
First, we're going
to put the sugar here,
the butter.
-Creaming the butter.
-Yeah.
Then, the tequila.
The eggs inside.
Flour?
Flour.
Okay, and then
the almond meal?
That's it.
[ Whirring ]
Okay. So, we're gonna
laminate this dough.
♪♪
And then, we're gonna
cut it, flip it.
♪♪
Put your hands here.
Just roll it very gently,
keep rolling.
All right, you stay here.
Dad and I are gonna leave.
FIERI: See you
in a little bit.
We'll be at the Alamo.
They left me again?
I gotta do all the work.
[ David laughs ]
Let's hurry up and cook these
before they get back.
You want to bake them
at 335 degrees
for 27 minutes.
♪♪
Man, you can bake
better than me.
I know, right?
Nicely done!
♪♪
Wow.
FIERI: That is
a really good croissant.
So good.
Before Ryder eats them all,
what's the next step?
David: We're going to put
the tequila syrup,
then the almond paste
that we did.
Okay.
Next, we're going to put
more almond paste in the top,
and we put some almonds.
How much more time are
we gonna bake those for?
10 1/2 minutes.
At what temperature?
395.
And this is one of
the number-one sellers?
It's the number-one
seller.
-It is the number one seller?
-It is the number one seller.
They look beautiful.
The final touch.
-Mm-hmm, powdered sugar.
-Mmm!
There you go.
♪♪
Mm!
It's really luxurious.
It's creamy.
It's not too much almond.
Yeah.
It's not too much sugar.
It's the right balance,
because you still get the nice,
light flakiness
of the croissant,
and the paste has
its own body.
And it didn't
just cook out.
Yeah.
You got a lot of things
going the right way.
Well, thank you.
Thank you.
That was awesome.
Very good.
Here you go, guys.
We've got the tequila
almond croissant.
You start with the outside.
It's nice and crispy.
And then you get
into the creamy inside.
Oh! On point.
-I mean, seriously.
-Absolutely amazing.
Makes you happy.
Here's a Hawaiana
with black bean soup.
This is like my number
one place to come eat.
There's just not anything
like it around.
FIERI: I've been
to thousands of restaurants.
What you and your brother
are doing,
and to the level
that you're doing it,
I mean, it's...
It's amazing.
Thank you.
Thank you so very much.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
a Michigan spot
where you can
dial up barbecue...
That's a real-deal
sandwich.
...Vietnamese...
You're doing it right.
...and a cell phone?
How does the cell phone store
have a restaurant baby?
FIERI: How are ya, brother?
[ Horn blares ]
We traded for the day.
♪♪
Yo, ladies and gentlemen,
we have found Triple D joints
in the craziest of places.
Of course, we've found them
in gas stations.
Well, we've found them
in a grocery store.
We've found it
in a liquor store.
Found it in an antiques store.
We've even found it
in a boxing gym.
But I gotta tell you what,
we're here in Lansing, Michigan,
just a few blocks
from the capital,
and this has got to be
the craziest one yet.
Inside of a cellular store?
This is Capital City Barbecue.
♪♪
I have the Awesome Mess
right here.
This is a Vietnamese, barbecue
cell phone fusion,
so it's extra unique.
Pho for table number five!
WOMAN: You can come in here
for a plan, an accessory,
and take some food to go.
FIERI: So, how did
the cell phone store have
a restaurant baby?
FIERI: At the time,
Linh Lee had started dating
Regan Louchart,
who worked as a contractor.
So, he helped her
rebuild the store
while also constructing
a culinary tag team.
♪♪
Brisket banh mi.
WOMAN: It is like
two restaurants in one,
but then you can also get
the mixture of the two,
like the brisket banh mi.
The meat is so melty,
but the vegetables
bring it back,
make it so crisp.
FIERI:
First up, brisket.
So, we're making
the dry rub.
We got cumin here,
chili powder,
granulated garlic,
onion powder.
Brown sugar?
Cayenne pepper,
kosher salt.
Whoa!
Look at him go!
There ya go.
[ Chuckles ] Hey!
Paprika, black pepper,
and a little bit
of white pepper.
What are you smoking
the brisket in?
The Southern Pride
smoker --
225,
four to five hours.
Now, we pull it
out of the smoker,
goes into another oven
and cooks for
another 16 hours.
So, brisket is done.
All right, Linh,
what's next?
Lemongrass that went
through a food processor.
Shallots.
Black pepper...
Sugar.
Okay.
I've had a lot
of Vietnamese food;
never had cola in it.
When they bite...
[ Sighs ]
Melt in their mouth.
How long's it going
to marinade for?
Overnight.
And what do we do next?
Pickled daikon.
Daikon.
White vinegar,
salt, sugar,
daikon in there.
Then, we dump in
the carrot.
What do we do next?
We're going to
make a sandwich!
Sriracha mayo.
Jalapenos.
Cucumber.
Green onion.
Pickled daikon
and carrots.
Cilantro.
Very nice.
♪♪
My heart is pumping.
You got good smoke,
good bark on the brisket.
♪♪
The marinade you made,
the brisket soaked it right up.
The pickled veggies
are great.
Little sriracha mayo.
That's a real-deal
sandwich --
No joking around
about that.
♪♪
Delicious.
Yeah.
All right,
I got a brisket banh mi.
There's all this flavor
when you take a bite.
MAN: The brisket's perfect.
Makes your mouth water.
Can't stop eating it.
Table number seven,
ready to go!
Linh's just so passionate
about her food.
♪♪
FIERI: Which is good
for the locals,
who are eating up
her homeland favorites.
The shrimp spring roll
and pork for table number eight!
It's got the pork and shrimp,
some vegetables.
And the peanut sauce
just puts it over the top.
Pork and shrimp spring roll?
Yeah.
I let this boil
about an hour and 30 minutes.
With the shell
on it.
Yes.
What happens in the shrimp
with the shell?
What happens?
Butterfly.
Like butterflies!
[ Laughter ]
A little olive oil
in there.
You're going to boil
off the noodles.
Yeah, for eight minutes.
Now?
Sriracha.
Now we're going to put
everything together?
Now the fun part.
Cucumber, lettuce,
mint, cilantro.
Noodles, gotcha.
Yeah.
Then I start rolling.
Tight as you can,
very nice.
♪♪
The mint's great.
Noodles are tender.
There's not too many ingredients
but there's enough.
And the shrimp
are great.
They're tender.
The veggies are fresh.
And the peanut sauce...
♪♪
...really good.
You're doing it right.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
♪♪
I can't leave without having
the spring rolls.
I just love
the fresh taste of it.
You put that peanut butter sauce
on top of that spring roll,
one of the best things
I ever tasted in my life.
Steer Clear, baked beans.
You come here once,
you're going to come here again.
I've never seen
a place like this.
I really dig it.
I think you guys are
a great couple,
and you...
are wild.
Thank you!
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry,
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country!
I'll see you next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives."
♪♪
Did you take a bite?
What is that?
Let's see a bite out of it.
Like a real...
[ Laughing ]
What a spaz.
[ Laughter ]