Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Laughs ]
...we're busing
into brisket...
That's full-blown
gangster.
...barbecue...
Gorgeous.
...and breakfast
with a twist...
Holla.
...because
this Los Angeles spot
is serving up morning
favorites late at night.
French toast crunchy
nuggets of happiness.
Plus, we're hitting
the smoker in Phoenix...
Nicely done.
...and a Columbus, Ohio, joint
is putting the "fun" in funky...
You don't play
by the rules.
...dialing up creative
culinary combos.
Nobody could have convinced me
it would be that good.
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives".
♪♪
You know, I think deep-down
inside, every food-truck owner
wants to have their own
brick-and-mortar.
We're here in Columbus, Ohio,
to check out a joint
where the food-truck owner went
and bought out
the local community market
and turned it into a place,
well, you probably won't forget.
This is Sweet Carrot.
♪♪
All right,
chicken kale soup, guys.
It's so unique here.
Artichokes on mac and cheese.
The food is top-notch.
And it's innovative.
Load that griddle, Tucker,
'cause we're getting busy.
As you walk in through the door,
the atmosphere
smacks you straight
in the face.
FIERI: It's the atmosphere
of creativity, food,
and fun that chef and owner
Angela Petro grew up on.
My mom and dad loved to
entertain...
Right.
...and so they would go out
and see live bands,
and then the whole band
would end up in our kitchen
and my dad would make
a giant skillet
of sausage gravy
and biscuits.
So, for me,
food's a big party.
So, it's no surprise that
she's rocked the catering world,
a food truck, and now her
own venue for her unique flair.
Ohio chicken
meatball sandwich.
The Ohio chicken meatball
sandwich here is fantastic.
It has a surprising
ginger-soy glaze to it.
All right,
what are we making?
Let's make our Ohio
chicken meatballs.
This has a little bit
of an Asian flavor.
I gotcha.
-Eggs.
-Sweet chili sauce.
-Teriyaki sauce.
-Okay.
I'm a freestyler, okay?
-There's no rules.
-Wiki-wiki.
-Dried ginger.
-Salt and pepper.
Whisk and scatter.
Locally sourced chicken.
How many meatballs
will this make?
Like a ton.
Oh.
[ Laughs ]
-Cilantro.
-Green onion.
Panko bread crumbs.
-You want it all?
-Yeah!
It's more fun that way.
We use a half-ounce scoop.
In the oven...
It's eight minutes
to bake them.
Bring them out,
hold them in the sauce.
In a sesame-ginger sauce.
-What do we make next?
-The corn salsa.
Well, you just make
a little bit of corn salsa.
-Just a little.
-Really just dabbling.
Fire it up.
Corn that we roast with cumin,
cayenne, chili powder,
smoked paprika,
and paprika.
This is good.
So now we're going to add
poblano, diced red onion,
cilantro,
red pepper,
green onion,
and fresh garlic.
Beautiful colors --
look at that.
We've got lime juice, salt and
pepper, and our dressing.
Dressing?
Mayonnaise, sour cream,
lime juice, and sugar.
-Got it.
-Then add my cheese blend.
So, this would sit
overnight.
So, that is it.
That's the go-to.
Spicy corn salsa.
Come and try some.
Those are gorgeous.
You make all your breads?
Breads, cookies, cakes --
everything from scratch.
What kind of bun is this?
This is a sweet-yeast roll --
very Southern style.
-That's full-blown gangster.
-Put some butter on it.
Now it grills.
Dig it.
Slice that sucker
right down the middle.
Five meatballs on that.
And this is a vinegar-based
coleslaw.
Got it.
Corn salsa, and then
we're going to top it off
with the same
sesame-ginger sauce...
-Okay.
-...that the meatballs are in.
Oh, that's the way --
you're first.
[ Laughs ]
I'm anticipating wearing
a lot of that.
[ Mumbles ]
Your meatball --
it's balanced,
it's got a good flavor
in it, tender.
Really, really good.
And then all the depth
and the crunch and the texture
of that corn salsa
with that slaw.
It is spot-on, and the bun
is phenomenal.
This is what I like about you --
you don't play by the rules.
This, if you ever told anybody
it was going to go together,
they'd go, "You're crazy".
But it works.
I'd order that again
for the next five years.
Awesome.
Two Ohio chicken-meatball
sandwiches.
It's a meatball day.
WOMAN: The meatballs
are nice and juicy.
It's a little bit sweet,
a little bit tangy.
And you need to get
the corn sauce on everything.
Anything, everything.
-That's just the way it is?
Yes.
FIERI: And you can!
'Cause at this place you start
with picking a base...
The homemade bun,
kale salad.
Griddled corn cake, mac and
cheese, which is my favorite.
Oh, that's
just what I need.
You gotta change the name
from Sweet Carrot
to "Fat Rabbit"
after that.
[ Laughs ]
Then you choose
how to top it off.
I have
the brisket corn cake.
Nice, moist corn cake
on the bottom,
topped with smoked
brisket in-house.
Divine.
Okay, let's talk
about brisket.
We're going to make
our house rub.
Okay.
Chipotle powder, crushed red
pepper flakes, sea salt,
dried minced onion,
raw sugar,
dry minced garlic,
and smoked paprika.
When you pull the brisket
out of the smoker...
Yes?
...this entire restaurant
smells amazing.
So, an untrimmed,
monster brisket.
We're going to coat this thing,
top to bottom, side to side.
Straight from dry rub
into the smoker?
For 15 hours.
-At?
-215.
Great bark, great crust.
Really good brisket.
-Thanks.
We also hit it with a couple of
ladles full of the natural jus.
Just what melts
off the brisket.
Then it keeps it
nice and moist.
Let's make a corn cake.
That's what
I was going to say.
Start with my cornmeal,
I'm going to add
a gluten-free cornbread mix.
Got it.
Sugar, double-acting
baking powder.
It's acting like baking
powder two times.
That's right.
Cayenne.
-Salt.
Now we're going to make
the wet part of the mix.
Start with eggs,
melted butter, whole milk.
We're going to add
the dry mix.
Now,
just plain corn in here.
-Plain corn.
-[ Chuckles ]
Really? I didn't know they
made a "Star Wars" edition.
Okay.
[ Blender whirs ]
I'm going to add the rest
of the corn,
mixed with some
fresh green onion.
Right on the flat-top.
It's like a savory pancake.
-Like it.
-Put our brisket on there.
Our coleslaw again...
-Okay.
...and our all-around condiment,
corn salsa.
Top it with our house-made
barbecue sauce.
Okay.
There's nothing that's
going to be sexy
about me picking that up
and eating this.
♪♪
Hmm.
That's ridiculous.
This corn cake is so light,
and so airy,
it's crisp,
it's got great moisture,
it's got the nuggets
of corn.
I want a dozen of
the cakes to go.
-Thanks.
-Great brisket.
No one could have convinced me
that it would be that good.
Brisket on a corn cake,
loaded.
It just brings that hardy
feeling of a comfort food.
It's like heaven in your mouth.
Cheesy chips and
mac and cheese balls.
Sweet Carrot's
a wonderful place to come.
Scratch made, creative,
one of a kind,
and you're doing it
in a really fun environment.
You're dangerous.
-Thanks, Guy.
♪♪
FIERI:
Up next, in Los Angeles...
Dude, trouble.
...a dinner-time spot
cooking up rise and shine...
There you go.
That's just fine.
...all with a grown-up spin.
Did we just become best friends
after this dish?
-I talk with my hands a lot.
-No kidding?
But I cook with my mouth,
which is really weird.
[ Laughs ]
I don't know
what just happened.
♪♪
So, do you remember
when you were a kid,
and your parents would say,
"What do you want for dinner?"
You'd say, "Hey, can we have
breakfast for dinner?"
And you meant it.
I mean, you were talking,
like, French toast and pancakes
and syrup and bacon
and whipped cream
and the whole thing.
Well, believe it or not, here
at Venice Beach, California,
there's a dude that's
doing it all the time.
It's a place you got
to check out --
that is, if you're
a kid at heart.
This is
Nighthawk Breakfast Bar.
Breakfast burger.
Breakfast food
for an evening time.
Pig's nest!
Super-fun, late night,
rock 'n' roll vibe.
This is all kinds
of "yes" for me.
I think it's odd when the
breakfast place opens at 6 p.m.
FIERI: But it makes sense
when you meet chef and owner,
Jeremy Fall, who has
a passion for kitchens
and late-night digs.
My mom owned restaurants
when I was growing up.
Okay.
I did everything --
bus boy, runner.
-You've done it all.
-The whole nine-yards.
I had this really weird, random
idea to do breakfast for dinner,
so I started writing
some ideas for dishes down.
I came up with some
weird cocktail ideas.
Have you had spiked cereal milk?
That's what we do here.
-Yeah, with the booze?
-Yeah.
I didn't know you were
actually allowed to do that.
But this dude's all about
pushing the envelope
on childhood favorites.
They put alcohol
in their French toast.
I got one
drunken French toast.
MAN: When you're looking for
something a little rich,
a little decadent,
try the French toast.
What are we making?
Pear compote for
the drunken French toast.
Can I get a milk crate?
Are you -- oh, you're
getting up on the crate?
So, anyhow...
[ Laughter ]
I'm light-headed --
the altitude, dude.
Let's fire it up.
We're gonna start
with the pears,
brown sugar, white sugar.
-There we go.
-Lemon juice.
-Okay.
-Cognac -- nice and heavy.
Let that burn off.
Pears are cooking down
to a nice syrup.
You're letting
all that great flavor
of that pear come through.
-What's next?
-You have the mascarpone mousse.
-Fantastic.
-Mascarpone.
A cross between whipped
cream and cream cheese.
You got a little bit tang,
a little bit light.
Add some honey to it.
Cardamom.
-Interesting.
Last but not least...
-Batter for the French toast.
-Okay.
Some heavy cream.
Here we go for some milk.
Because heavy cream
by itself is just too much.
Add some eggs.
You want to just drink --
Oh!
I do, I just got it,
but I'm trying to cut down.
Yeah, yeah.
That's how I'm keeping this
together.
Real vanilla abstract,
and some cinnamon.
And then you want to do
the honors on the booze --
pear brandy.
-Betcha it isn't.
Yep, it is.
-Yep.
-That's good brandy.
You have the whimsical side
of what you're doing,
but you're also paying attention
to quality, method, ingredients.
We like taking stuff
like classics
that people already like,
and kind of tweaking them,
and putting our take
on it.
The batter's rather to go.
Yes, sir.
And now, we take--
-We're doing challah bread.
-Holla.
-You want to dip it deep.
Whoa!
You're going real deep.
-Throw it on --
-Crispy cereal?
Yeah. You want to kind of
get it on there.
Look at that, dude.
That's a full mess
you just made.
Where do you want
the butter?
-Right there.
-Right here?
My son Ryder is
going bananas right now.
So, we're going to let this
cook on both sides,
get a nice little
crunch to it.
-Exactly.
-Gorgeous.
Nice, puffy -- I like
the way this is rolling.
I'm going to slice it.
Flip it.
French toast, crunchy
nuggets of happiness.
Exactly.
Then you're going to take
the mascarpone.
You kind of want to play it,
almost like a football, right?
-Cornell?
-Sure.
Actually, that's a classy
way of putting it.
We've over at Nighthawk making
up some mascarpone footballs.
The pear compote
we made earlier.
You guys got any muumuus
for sale out front?
-More of that pear brandy.
-That's just great.
Maple syrup,
powdered sugar.
There you go.
That's just fine.
So, I get
the perfect bite here.
Nice crust,
but the squishy,
spongy deliciousness
of the challah owns it.
Pears are great. The brandy kiss
really matures the thing.
The key that ties it together is
the silky fat of the mascarpone.
And then, without question,
the little,
crunchy niblets
on the outside.
That's a mature
French toast.
Seriously, well done.
-Thank you.
Composed.
All right, table four --
I need one drunken French toast.
I've not had French toast
like this before.
The pear brandy on there...
-Is ridiculous.
-Absolutely killer.
We have it for dessert
all the time.
What do you think
of this place?
Pretty solid, dude.
WOMAN: This place is
definitely addicting --
the food, the vibes,
everything.
We're hanging out
in Venice Beach, California
at a funky joint
called Nighthawk.
When we come back, we're going
to make a pork belly?
-Biscuit bao.
-Exactly.
-Pork belly in the biscuit?
Perfect mixture.
-See you in a bit.
I'll finish this up.
♪♪
Welcome back, "Triple D" hanging
out in Venice Beach, California,
where we're just two blocks
from the beach
in a funky joint
called Nighthawk,
where you can get
breakfast for dinner.
Dude, trouble.
You got the duck fired
for the purple haze?
I've tried a lot of
the things on the menu,
and they all surprised
me in a good way.
One biscuit bao
for table 12.
The biscuit bao
is delicious.
Pork-belly stuffed biscuit with
the sweet chilli sauce on top
is really nice.
We're going to start
by rubbing the belly.
Biscuit bao,
then rubbing the belly?
rubbing the belly.
So, we have paprika,
onion powder.
-Got it.
-Tri-color peppercorn.
Coriander.
-Granulated garlic.
Salt. So, you want to kind of
spread the rub
so that it gets everywhere.
Pour the marinade out
on top of it.
White wine, soy sauce,
fish sauce.
I'm a big fish sauce fan.
-Onions.
-Bay leaf.
-Thyme.
-Just past 10:00.
Thank you.
Star anise, garlic.
Cina-mon-amon-amon-amon?
Coriander?
-Yes, but not ground this time.
And a little bit of water.
-All right.
Wrap it in plastic, cover it
with foil, put it in the oven.
-What temp?
-325.
Bring it out.
It's cooled down, you've cubed
it, so we got all this nice fat.
I'm just going to try
this for science.
It's an experiment.
That's going to be fine.
Grilled onions.
These are the meat dice
at Flavortown casino.
[ Indistinct ] cheese.
Salt. Sweet soy.
-Gochujang?
-Gochujang.
Where does the Korean
influence come in?
It's kind of inspired by
the Californian melting pot,
you know,
that we have here.
Got it.
Quickly throw it in the fryer
for one minute.
We're just going to
blast-fry this.
Let it cool, chop it,
and that's how I make
the filling for the biscuit bao.
All right,
so our pork is done.
We're going to make
biscuit dough.
Okay.
So, AB flour, cold butter cube.
Butter milk, salt, sugar.
There we go, Vanna.
There we -- oh!
-Baking powder.
And then we're actually gonna
add the cheddar and chive after,
so that you don't
press the chive --
To be a "chive-turkey".
Cheddar cheese and chive --
I'll let you do the honors.
There we go.
And then you're going
to mix it all in.
Bench flour down.
It's about two ounces
of dough per biscuit.
I'm going to flatten it, take a
scoop of pork-bellied filling...
And then you just fill it.
Make it round.
So, you're going to a little bit
of the maple sambal glaze
that we make here.
-Maple sambal glaze.
In the oven how long?
-20 minutes, 325.
Dig it, brother.
Now bow.
-He gets the joke.
-Did we do it at the same time?
-The exact same time.
-It looks like we practiced it,
but you didn't actually
practice that.
Fortunately, you're taller than
me, so we didn't hit heads.
-Sambal glaze.
-And what have we got here?
I've got picked daikon radishes,
pickled carrots --
[ Laughs ]
-Put the bao on top.
-Okay.
We're going to top it off with
maple sambal glaze, as well.
Added to a Southern biscuit,
with French cheese.
This is kind of like
the U.N. of bao buns.
Yes. Yeah.
♪♪
Did we just become
best friends after this dish?
The biscuit is nice,
light, and flaky --
just what you want
out of a biscuit.
The pork belly is truly
identifiable,
and you get the fat.
You haven't cooked it
down so much
to where
it's shredding apart.
Got a little kiss
of the sambal
with just a little
bit of the maple.
Am I Asian?
Am I Southern?
It's just all the components.
That right there, brother...
-Thanks, Guy.
-...well done.
-Thank you.
One biscuit bao.
-It has a good kick.
I love it.
-It's fresh, it's not too heavy.
It's got a great,
all-around taste to it.
I got one purple haze.
The food is just spot-on
every time.
What first attracted me
to Nighthawk
was the booze-y cereal.
Then I started seeing
food that was either going to be
all-hype and no deliver, or
it was going to be outstanding.
But what you have done,
is you've done it legit.
People come here for the concept
because it's a little bit weird,
but they come back for the food
because it's good.
Watch out!
FIERI:
Coming up in Phoenix...
Da-da-da.
-Da-da-ta.
...a barbecue spot piling up
the prime rib...
That's my kind
of French dip.
...a dish with dumplings
that are out-of-bounds.
A spaceship
from Flavor Town?
Spaceship to Flavor Town.
♪♪
I'm here in old-town
Scottsdale, Arizona,
and I tell you, man,
you can get it done down here.
You've got a bunch of shops.
You can hear great music.
And if you're looking
for something to eat,
do not worry --
there's all kinds of joints,
like this place,
where they're smoking
just about everything.
This is Bootleggers.
♪♪
SLADE: Boot burger.
It's barbecue meets
New American gastropub.
Green chili pork tacos.
Just down-home good cookin'.
Order of chicken wings,
get 'em out of here.
WOMAN: This place is
completely different,
say, to other restaurants
in the Scottsdale area.
FIERI: That's because
the kitchen's manned
by a pretty unique
dude, Kevin Slade,
who found his calling
on the barbecue circuit.
It was good food, it was good
people, it was late at night.
It's a brotherhood.
Yeah, I as like,
"I have arrived".
Started competing,
traveling around, led to this.
MAN:
They feature barbecue, but they
have all kinds of things
that you would never expect.
SERVER:
We got the boot dumplings.
I love the dumplings --
it has the shrimp and the pork.
It's a perfect combination of
crispy, smokey, sweet, savory.
What are we making?
Our boot dumpling -- kind of
random for a barbecue place.
All right, let's see it.
Kind of nice.
Start with the rub.
Paprika, garlic powder.
Got red chili,
achiote pepper, dry mustard.
Is this similar to the
competition rub you were using?
It's really pretty close,
but, you know, everybody's got
their little high-tech,
like, super-secret deals.
Garlic, black pepper.
This is our house rub.
-All right.
We use this on our brisket.
We use it on our pork.
We use it on our pork-belly.
How about we just say
what you don't use it on?
The cereal?
-Yeah!
We're going to score
the pork belly, dry rub it.
We let it sit for
about two hours.
And then we'll go into
the smoker for how long?
Eight hours seems
to be the number.
We cook it around 210, 212.
Gorgeous.
Put it in the walk-in,
let it cool down.
-What are we into?
-House-made barbecue sauce.
We use it for
our chipotle-mango sauce.
Starting with ketchup,
brown sugar, liquid smoke.
Apple-cider vinegar.
Pureed onions, cooked in butter.
Worcester sauce,
say it right with me.
-Wash-your-sister's-house.
-Wor-she-shaw-shosh.
Nash-nah.
-Molasses.
-Paprika.
Onion and garlic.
-Mustard and black pepper.
-There it is.
You let it boil,
bring it down to a simmer,
let it sit
for about two hours.
Mango chipotle
barbecue sauce.
-Some chipotle?
-Start this with mango.
Sweet pepper sauce.
House-made barbecue sauce.
Minced ginger.
Add some chipotle
in adobo.
That's it.
And that is our sauce we use
for the boot dumpling.
I'll take 10 gallons
of that, please.
You all right?
That's where ten-gallon hat
came from, is that.
That's it.
"I'll take ten gallons of that."
"Did you say 'ten-gallon hat'?"
In a hat?
Wait a minute.
So, we took the pork belly
down to a paste,
and now we're going
to build
the rest of the ingredients
for a filling.
That's where we're at.
Shrimp, cilantro, cumin,
garlic powder, onion powder,
black pepper, salt.
We're going to take
a pastry.
-Won ton skin.
-Egg wash.
Then we take our filling,
set that on the dumpling.
-Boom.
-Spaceship from Flavor Town?
Spaceship to Flavor Town.
That's right.
-[ Laughs ]
-Got it.
We steam them for
about 30 seconds.
Then we finish them off
on the flat top.
Mango chipotle
barbecue sauce.
A little beet reduction.
Got the boot dumplings.
Add micro greens.
♪♪
Talk to me.
You put the perfect sear
on it.
You get a little bit
of the smoke.
And you give a nice,
little mix of everything,
in contrast to the barbecue
sauce and the sweet sauce.
Nicely done.
-Yeah, brother.
-Nicely done.
-The dumplings.
They're the best dumplings
I've ever had, for sure.
MAN: You can taste every
ingredient from the smoke
to the pork belly
to the shrimp,
until you get the little heat
on the mango-chipotle sauce.
-Dumplings are steaming.
-Kevin's awesome.
I remember helping him
at the barbecue fest.
The biggest competition
you won?
I beat Johnny Trigg
in ribs.
Johnny Trigg's my boy,
dude!
He took sixth
and I took fifth.
-Dude, let me just --
-That's all that mattered!
I didn't care about
anything else.
I just got to say,
I beat him by one slot.
Listen, the guy is
the godfather of barbecue.
Real deal.
BBLT at the bar.
It's so easy to get
hooked on this place.
Favorite things
on the menu?
-Hmm.
-Oh, "hmm"?
Oh, the "hmm" --
I love "hmm".
MAN: The dip, I love it.
MAN #2: Prime rib
on that smoker over there.
From Kevin -- it's the bomb.
What are we going
to make next, buddy?
The French dipped sandwich
out of the prime rib.
-I like it.
-House rub, thyme.
Did you meet
my friend rosemary?
-Da-da-da.
-Da-da-ta.
Garlic oil.
This wet rub's going to go
on top of this,
and how long is this going
to sit before it goes in?
Three to four hours
is good.
Bring out the flavor.
-Let it work.
It smokes
for about four hours.
We like it pretty much more rare
than medium-rare.
Okay. So everybody gets this --
most prime ribs are not smoked.
So, the amount of flavor
you're adding to this
already delicious piece
of meat is outstanding.
That rub works
really well on there.
All right, Spicoli,
what's up?
Au jus
for the French dip.
-Okay.
-Water and beef base.
Whole garlic.
Bay leaf.
Peppercorns.
Thyme.
Let it reduce
about two hours.
Au jus -- that's what we put
our meat in for our French dip.
We're just trying to bring
that up to temp.
Not to cook it
any further.
That's it.
Horseradish sauce.
Okay, coming over.
That's the au jus.
-Nicely done.
-Slice it,
show it, try it.
♪♪
The horseradish cream -- I think
any time you serve a prime-rib
French dip, you got
to have a little acid
to cut the richness
of all that fat.
And just enough bread
when you're dipping it
into that much jus...
it soaks it up.
It turns it into, like,
a soup sandwich.
The meat cooked to medium rare,
just warmed up in the jus.
That's my kind
of French dip.
-Glad you enjoyed it.
-Well done.
-Thanks, brother.
-The French dip?
The mix of the salty,
hardy prime rib with the au jus
is just hard to beat.
Melts in your mouth,
great smoke flavor.
SERVER: The nacho flat.
This is absolutely one
of my favorite places
in the Scottsdale area.
-Brisket up!
The atmosphere's amazing
and the food is delicious.
-Give it up for the man, huh?
-Thanks, man.
You did great.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry, there's
plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
-More barbecue stuff on it.
-♪ Sweet ♪
♪ Pepper sauce ♪
♪ Uh, oh, oh ♪
Thank you.
[ Laughter ]