I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
This trip...
Activate flavor jets.
...we're visiting
some new places...
Hi, food coma,
my name's Guy.
...of some familiar
"Triple-D" faces...
You're crazy, dude.
Like a primo pizza joint
in Flagstaff...
Look at that! Come on.
...a killer waterfront spot
in Fairhope, Alabama...
Oh, I can feel the magic.
...and in Miami...
Phenomenal.
...a chef dialing up
the funk factor
with his spin on Chinese.
I can't figure out how to
get it in my face fast enough.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here in a familiar
area of Miami.
You see, just four years ago,
I was right across the street
over there at Sakaya Kitchen.
Now, when that was happening,
the chef was opening
a new restaurant
across the street.
I said, "Dude, one day
I'll be back."
I hold my end of the deal.
This is Black Brick.
♪♪
The Peking Duck.
Just a wonderful
take on Chinese food.
Pick up, General Tso's Gator.
You'll never make anything
like this at home.
Two minutes out on my rice.
One of my favorite chefs.
Sakaya is still one of my
all-time favorite restaurants.
GUY: That's Richard Hales'
take on Asian soul food.
Now he's mixing his
funky roots with Chinese,
here at Black Brick.
I mean, I'm half-Filipino,
I'm half-Irish,
I'm half-Italian.
That's --
that's too many halves.
And this is my version of,
like, Szechuan and Hunan.
He's come up with dishes
that I haven't found
in any other Chinese restaurant.
Jennifer, pick up,
dan dan noodles.
It has this peanut sauce
that is really, really good.
And the pork on top, and they're
spicy, they're amazing.
Making dan dan?
I'm mixing my Italian
background in this,
so we're going to extrude
a bucatini noodle.
So you're going to
throw a little bit
more funk to the dish.
Right.
So this is a high-gluten flour,
water, a little bit of salt.
You knead it first,
three or four minutes.
Okay.
And then, once it starts to
pull together, we'll extrude it.
♪♪
You twist 'em up into a nest,
and you're dropping
fresh noodles
every day to make
the dan dan.
Every day.
Now we're into making
the Szechuan pork.
-Lots of oil.
-Crank those BTUs, homeslice.
So I want to drain the meat.
So you just keep
that working pot of fat?
Yeah.
So we're back in
with the pork fat.
Chili bean paste, so this
is a fermented chili bean.
Then we have chili oil,
which we make in-house.
-Okay.
-Fresh ginger, fresh garlic.
Just want to cook this for,
like, one or two minutes.
-Next.
-I'm gonna add my pork back.
Active flavor jets.
[ Flame whooshes ]
-Chicken seasoning.
-White pepper.
-White pepper. Hoisin.
-Load it up!
This is Chinese Shaoxing
cooking wine.
Little deglaze from that.
-Cayenne. Sesame oil.
-What's this?
This is numbing oil.
GUY: The peppers in the oil sort
of give it a numbing feeling,
but it's actually filled
with flavorful spices.
Check it for "prosperity."
Oh, it's so good.
I'm getting the tongue numb.
Let's make some dan dan
for some Guy Guy.
-We have our noodles cooked.
-Gorgeous.
A little of our peanut sauce
and our meat sauce.
-Oil and all?
-Yeah.
We do a little crushed peanuts,
some toasted sesame seeds,
and then a little scallions.
Hi, food coma, my name's Guy.
♪♪
I'm going to tell you, Chef.
This has got to be,
without question,
one of my favorites
you ever made.
The chili oil you make
is the key to that.
Right.
Your discipline comes
through in this dish.
Respect to the noodle,
respect to the ingredients,
to the balance.
You don't cut any corners.
Real deal, authentic.
Crushed that.
Dude, I mean,
like lights-out good.
Thank you.
I can't figure out how to get
it in my face fast enough.
Your dan dan noodles.
I will have the noodles
any day of the week.
I spent six years in China
and this is, like,
right up there
with the best over there.
Being half-Chinese, it does feel
a little bit like home.
All right, I'm going with the
gator with that char sui bao.
how long?
WOMAN: It was a really
rough neighborhood,
and Richard opened Sakaya
and really helped
bring people to the area.
And then, with Black Brick,
I mean, it really took it
to a whole other level.
Pick up, cumin lamb chops!
The cumin lamb chops have
such a distinctive taste.
They have a nutty,
earthy spice to them.
So this is the spice blend
from my cumin lamb chop.
You start out with cumin,
fennel, grains of paradise,
and some chili flakes
that I toast it and I ground.
Ginger, garlic, chicken base,
paprika, cayenne,
Szechuan peppercorns
that are toasted and ground.
-Whoa!
-Black pepper
and then
a little bit of salt.
Ohh!
Next step?
So these are New Zealand
lamb chop.
Add our spice blend
that we just made.
Which I'm taking some home.
Fresh scallions, corn starch.
I think corn starch was
invented for Chinese food.
I think it was.
Chicken base.
Shaoxing wine.
Black pepper.
Fermented black beans.
Okay.
Soy sauce, and a little
bit of baking soda.
Really?
Yeah. That's gonna cause
a reaction for that.
Marinate it for 24 hours, dredge
'em in the potato starch,
then we're going
to fry it to order --
medium-rare, medium.
A little flavored mayonnaise
with cilantro,
some of the spice.
-Is this a normal portion?
-This is a normal portion here.
-A whole rack?
-A whole rack.
We're going to add back
our spice blend on top
to fortify that layer.
This is jalapeño,
some Tianjin chilis,
quickly blanched with some
white and green onions,
and then fresh cilantro.
♪♪
Wow.
That flavor goes all the way
through that lamb.
I mean, with the cumin...
It's rich,
it doesn't taste fried.
It is so juicy.
I would order that
every single time.
Whew.
You have your
cumin lamb chops.
-How is that lamb?
-Oh, this is fantastic.
Perfectly seasoned with a
little bit of chili powder --
I think it's awesome.
So moist and delicious,
they're amazing.
Talk about familiar faces.
We visited Miami Smokers, and
these dudes are blowing it up.
Now have you been to
Black Brick before?
We have, we have.
One of the best chefs
in Miami.
Without question.
Char sui bao, in the window.
It's absolutely fantastic
every time we come.
Phenomenal.
You do nothing halfway.
Brother, you're the best.
Thank you.
♪♪
Next up...
[ Whistles ]
...a cat we first met
doing Mexican in Flagstaff...
You're the real deal, man.
...who's taken a culinary U-turn
with outrageous woodfired pies.
My friend, as always,
you do not disappoint.
♪♪
I'm here in Flagstaff, Arizona,
and I'm actually on
vacation with my family,
but, yes, I'm stopping
to do a "Triple D."
Why? Because I got a buddy
named John Conley --
you remember him, Salsa Brava,
he was on "Triple D" years ago.
-[ Whistles ]
-[ Laughs ]
Also competed on "Triple G."
Well, if you knew the way
this dude cooks,
you'd be stopping at
his new restaurant too.
This is Fat Olives.
♪♪
I got a Belgio Dolce
and a Kenai, please.
The food is kind of addicting.
GUY: And a 180 for chef
and owner John Conley,
who turned this neighborhood
into a taste bud tug of war
when he opened his second joint
just down the street
from his first.
WOMAN: If you want the best
Mexican food in town,
you're going to go
to Salsa Brava.
If you're wanting the Italian
feel, you going to get
a really authentic
Italian pizza at Fat Olives.
They have the Neapolitan
certification.
To be a true Neapolitan
pizzeria, you have to use...
Bufala mozzarella.
You have to have
a woodfired oven.
We do -- it was made in Italy.
You have to use Caputo flour.
-Caputo or "00."
-Let's make this happen.
All right, so we're going
to add ice to our water.
Want to do a slow ferment.
This is Sicilian sea salt.
Now I'm going to put 30 pounds
of the flour into the mix.
Hang on, hang on, hang on,
just pour it in over
the hamster cage.
This flour comes from Italy.
Sometimes it gets humidity,
so this helps break it down.
Now we're going to add
the activated yeast.
We're going to let that run
for five minutes
and then we're going to add the
additional 30 pounds of flour.
-We let this go for 30 minutes.
-All right.
Bench it on the table
and let it rest
for about 15 minutes.
We do a 30-hour slow ferment,
a cold ferment.
GUY: And then it's ready
for toppings --
everything from traditional...
I got a pepperoni!
...to off-the-rails.
Belgio Dolce coming in.
Ever since I tasted
the Belgio Dolce pizza,
that's what we order
every single time.
There's items on there
that you would never think
to put on a pizza.
Who knew brussel sprouts
was perfect?
Okay, boss.
We're doing
Calabrian chili oil,
it's used on
our brussel sprouts.
So we're taking
chile de árbol.
It's going to go in
the woodfired oven for, like,
five seconds
until they're toasted.
What kind of wood
are you using?
Oak for heat and juniper
for the lick.
-For the lick.
-Lick!
The lick is the flame
coming over the top.
So we got these nice,
toasted chile de árbol.
Take a big hit of that.
Whoa.
We're going to pulse this with
some of the Calabrian chili oil.
Oh, I'm so
taking some of his home.
Chile de árbol.
And we're going to put them
into the blended oil.
All right, Calabrian chili
goes in there.
Oh, those Calabrian
chilis are so good.
Love them.
Let me pour the oil in it too.
You're the man.
In goes
the Calabrian chili oil.
Cover it up and put it
to bed for seven days.
Then strain it through
cheese cloth.
Yep.
Calabrian chili's going
into the brussel sprouts --
it's going to set
for about four hours.
Got it.
So now we're going to make
the Belgio Dolce.
-Boy, that is just tender.
-Yeah.
Start with a white base --
cream, butter,
our house-made mozzarella,
a little oregano.
-Sicilian?
-Sicilian.
Soppressata
and Calabrian chili oil,
shaved brussel sprouts.
Ahh!
Into our oven, 90 seconds.
Give it a little kiss up top.
-A little dome time.
-Let's see it.
Look at that! Come on.
We're going to finish it
with a little bit of pistachio,
local mesquite honey,
Calabrian chili oil.
Okay. [ Whistles ]
Cut it right on the plate.
My friend, as always,
you do not disappoint.
So Calabrian chili oil
and the honey --
that combo, the balance
between the sweet,
that little saltiness
of the pistachio --
your mouth is just confused the
entire time you're eating this.
The dough in this pizza is nice
and light, the char on it
really sets it off.
That is a dynamite pizza.
Well, this is John's son Adam.
He gets his good looks
from me.
And he's a wrestler.
I think you could wrestle
your son to the ground.
He's afraid, actually.
[ Laughing ]
He's so scared.
All right, Adam,
tell me what you think.
Mm! Oh wow.
It tastes nutty.
It is nutty.
This is definitely
a home run, Dad.
I would give it about 12 stars.
[ Laughs ]
-12 stars!
-I got 12 stars.
-Adam-certified.
-[ Laughs ]
Here's a Belgio Dolce.
The pizza's really flavorful,
the crust is just how I like it.
Brussel sprouts -- amazing.
A little bit of crunch
of the pistachios on top,
just makes it a really
well-rounded pizza.
WOMAN: It's a really great place
to come together
to enjoy great food,
but also a sense of community.
GUY: Which is why John is so key
to my "Triple D" alumni family,
along with our mutual buddy,
the late, great
Mike "Hodad" Hardin.
I love you, man,
you're the bomb.
[ Laughs ]
Thanks, brother.
You ought to see the tribute
we did to him at Salsa Brava.
I had previously been doing
this tour with the military.
These guys took it even
a step farther
and created a group
called the Messlords.
Hodad was a really big
piece of it, and I mean,
I'll start crying
about it right now.
Your appreciation
of life, family,
the way you take
care of people --
it really represents
in the food that you make.
Everything here
is the real deal.
Pesto spaghetti working.
Like too legit to...?
I won't quit.
It's too legit, I won't quit.
It's not like pizza
you get anywhere else.
Here comes the Kenai.
If you love salmon,
have the Kenai pizza.
Mixed with some creamy
dill sauce.
-Best pizza on the menu.
-What are we making next?
The house-smoked salmon
for our Kenai pizza.
Now where's the salmon
coming from?
The Copper River Delta,
a river called the Eyak.
What was the fish's name?
Sammy...Hagar.
[ Rim shot ]
That's a good-looking
piece of fish.
We're going to make
a brine for it. Water.
Sicilian sea-salt,
brown sugar --
let it do a flash brine
for about four hours.
Got it.
We're going to add the hickory
chips to the smoking pan.
The salmon into
the perforated pan.
We season it with
our house seasoning
and we're gonna put it on the
stovetop for eight minutes.
So you're just going to
perfume it with smoke?
-Yep.
-That's delicious.
Now we're going to
make the Kenai.
You got our white base --
housemade mozzarella.
First time we ever made mozz
was by Panini Pete's.
Yeah, he's got
a great restaurant.
I'm going to have to go do
Panini Pete's new place now.
That "Triple D" family --
we all get to share.
All right, now we add
some ricotta, pecorino romano,
and a little bit
of Italian oregano.
-90 seconds.
-There we go.
Our house-smoked salmon,
a little bit of fresh dill,
some red onion,
and house-made dill cream.
Gorgeous.
This is redonkulous.
I love that you didn't put the
salmon on the pizza in the oven.
That would have killed it.
The fresh dill, lights out.
The onion, of course,
with salmon.
You love that combo.
Mmm.
You could have that
breakfast, lunch, or dinner.
The effort, the enthusiasm,
the passion --
all of that comes
through in that pizza.
You're crazy, dude.
[ Laughs ]
Kenai pizza.
The salmon, it's just perfect,
it's like, "Wow, unexpected."
It's a wonderful
combination of flavors.
It's the food that you want
to come back to.
You're the real deal, man.
Congratulations.
-I really appreciate it.
-The bomb.
♪♪
GUY: Coming up...
Remember how we just
mentioned Panini Pete?
Dig this.
Well, we're hitting
his new place in Fairhope,
Alabama...
Finally, time to eat.
...where he's gone
from sandwiches
to show-stopping seafood.
Not good, not great --
dynamite.
I just crushed it
at this guy's new place.
-What's happening, brah? Ahh!
-Oh!
Anyhow, we just wanted to call
and say "Hi" and, uh...
-You should tell him.
-You probably don't care,
but we're just going to come do
"Triple D"
at Sunset Pointe if that's okay.
-Ah!
I think he just threw his phone.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So I'm here in Fairhope,
Alabama -- man, it's been years
since the last time I was here,
and I checked out a funky little
joint called Panini Pete's.
Well, subsequently, he's become
a really good buddy of mine,
and I'm cruising
through the area,
so you know what I gotta do.
Check out his new joint.
This is Sunset Pointe.
♪♪
Have the Gulf Coast
barbecue shrimp, ma'am.
Good-quality seafood --
it's really a great,
kept secret down
here in Alabama.
Yo, lettuce wrap --
give me a runner.
People that don't know
about this are missing out.
Baldwin County collard
greens, here we go.
Did you expect that the food
would be outstanding here?
Knowing him, yes.
And knowing "Triple D" classic
character Pete Blohme,
a.k.a. Panini Pete,
I can honestly say
this dude is the real deal.
So when he says he's going
from his sandwich joint
to opening a new seafood spot,
you know he means business.
So what was the inspiration?
Growing up in South Florida,
waterfront restaurants
are where I cut my teeth.
It's all fresh
and local seafood
and you can tell
when you taste it.
Grilled snapper, throats up.
He said, "Okay, you have to have
the snapper throat,"
and I went,
"Are you kidding me?"
It's really a phenomenal
piece of meat
that comes out of that fish.
A part of the fish that normally
people just throw out.
Best thing I've ever
had in my life.
This is the pride of the Gulf
Coast right here, red snapper.
If you hang around
in the marinas...
What is this? Does this
mean hanging around?
Yeah, hang around down
by the waterside, all right?
And what a lot of people don't
know is the best cut of the fish
is the collar or the throat.
Collar sounds sexier
than throat.
A lot of deckhands chop
this part of the fish off.
They're going to skin off
that filet, they'll give it
to the people that they
chartered the boat for,
and it's, "See ya later."
"See ya later."
You want to get in here
under these gills.
There's nothing
but meat there.
I can feel the magic.
"Hey, kids, who wants
some popcorn?"
"I want snapper throat!"
A little bit of oil,
this is a little
Cajun blackening medley
that we have.
Going to go on the grill
the bone side down,
probably eight minutes
while we work on the sides.
Okay, what are these sides?
We've got our Israeli couscous
and our collard greens.
We hit it with a little garlic
first, both of these, shallots.
We're going to add
in our sausage, couscous.
Is that mustard seed
I'm seeing in there?
A little bit of quinoa.
Quinoa inside of it,
collard greens.
We blanch them off first,
chop them up and season it up,
little stock.
-Okay.
-That's vegetable stock.
-Love it.
Salt and pepper --
we gotta season them.
A little cider vinegar on the
greens to give it a little pop.
Gonna flip your fish?
I'm going to give
that a little spin.
-Kind of Dutch oven them.
-Dig this.
All right, are we ready?
Finally, time to eat.
So we'll start off
with our couscous, greens.
The South, Mom will be happy
if you eat your greens.
All right, now we got
our snapper throat.
Crisp it up nice.
And then I got a nice, little
garlic butter over here --
we sauté some garlic,
shallots, softened butter,
some parsley,
a little bit of seasoning.
A little charred lemon.
That's the snapper throat.
Dig in --
great, great fish.
It's really good.
You're probably
going to love it.
Look at that nugget.
Done?
I'll -- I'll go away
right now.
I got to clean the grill
or something.
♪♪
The depth of flavor of the fish
in this area is remarkable.
It's tender, but you
got a good chew.
That little kiss of the fry
that you get at the end.
There's almost, like, almost
a little pocket of, like,
dark meat in there, too,
that's got that
extra depth of flavor.
You're hitting that
right now.
Couscous is a nice touch.
And those greens --
I'm not kidding you --
are out of bounds.
You're doing it the right way.
It's a great dish, buddy.
Thank you, thank you.
All right, guys, grilled Gulf
Coast snapper throats for you.
The meat is just the sweetest.
WOMAN: I like the crispiness
of the outside,
but it has the light,
flaky fish on the inside,
and it's an awesome dish.
WOMAN: Even though Fairhope
is surrounded by water,
there are only a couple of
places where you can go eat
on the water,
and this is absolutely the best.
MAN:
They have a little tradition
here where they ring the bell
when the sun goes down,
everybody toasts.
-Cheers.
-Cheers!
What else you got?
All right, we're going to do
some Eastern Shore
bouillabaisse.
How about this?
I give you plenty of time
to get yourself all ready.
-I'll get ready.
-Okay?
When we come back,
you'll make it?
All right, so here's the deal --
we're hanging out with
Panini Pete at his new place,
Sunset Pointe,
in Fairhope, Alabama.
When we come back, we're going
to make another dish.
Flavortown times two.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're at the famous
Panini Pete's -- no, we're not.
That's Pete's last joint
that we visited,
where we first met
this crazy character.
We're at Panini Pete's new joint
called Sunset Pointe.
From day one of opening,
and he said,
"You gotta come see it,
gotta come see it."
It really is a great place.
GUY: By land or by sea,
this is the place
to get some serious seafood.
Eastern Shore bouillabaisse
up, Nick, get it going.
He has the best bouillabaisse
that I've ever had.
We're working on a fish stock,
which we use
in a lot of our dishes,
mainly the Eastern Shore
bouillabaisse.
Oil, carrots.
Adorn it with
a little red onions.
Celery in there, too. We use
a lot of fennel in that dish.
Then once those veggies
sweat out a little bit,
we add our fish scraps.
So you're getting bones
and meat --
both are working
for the flavor, got it.
Yeah, absolutely.
Little bay leaf.
[ Whistles ]
And water.
Does it have to have
the whistle each time?
It just doesn't work
the same without it.
[ Whistles ]
Is that one of --
[ Stammers ]
[ Whistling, clicking ]
Water.
-How long is this going to go?
-Ten hours.
Okay, take it, strain it,
and that's going to be
the foundation
for this bouillabaisse.
Eastern Shore bouillabaisse.
We start with a nice,
hot pan, a little oil,
hit it with some shallots,
a little garlic.
-I got some fish.
-Great.
Gulf Coast shrimp.
Salt and pepper.
-Some mussels.
-Okay.
Some white wine.
A little deglaze on that.
Leeks, a little fennel bulb.
Okay.
I just like that
to get a little bit
of a subtle complexity
from that broth.
-You're a subtle complexity.
-Absolutely.
All right, now I got to get
some fish stock in.
-Got red and green tomatoes.
-Okay.
Now we're going to mount it
with a little butter.
Okay.
Some parsley --
this is very simple,
just tastes like the ocean.
Bet it tastes good.
♪♪
All right,
mussels go down first.
Here it comes, here it comes!
Yeah, a little more
parsley.
Our grilled bread
with a classic roux
that we kind of put
a little twist on.
It's got lemon aioli, bread
chunks, roasted peppers,
and some roasted corn.
-Fresh cracked pepper.
-Bring it all together.
-Absolutely.
-Dig this.
These babies go right in here.
There it is, the Eastern Shore
bouillabaisse.
♪♪
What are you doing?!
I was just cleaning up
over here.
♪♪
Do you normally want people
to season this at the table?
No.
Good, 'cause they shouldn't,
it's outstanding.
I knew it was coming!
The stock in this
is ridiculous.
Not overcooked, nice and tender
seafood, flaky fish.
It's light,
super deep in flavor.
♪♪
Not good, not great --
dynamite.
Bouillabaisse in the window.
It's succulent,
it's mouthwatering.
It's got a very light,
creamy taste to it. Very good.
Park your boat, come up and eat,
have fantastic drinks,
and watch the sunset.
It's just a great place to go.
You know, everybody knows you
for being the great
panini master,
but what I think
a lot of people don't know --
all the classically
trained talent that you have.
And, fortunately, you got
this great canvas
of all this fresh seafood
right here.
-Love you, brother. Congrats.
-Thank you.
♪♪
So that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
If you want to get some of the
recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives"!
How long have you
been coming here?
[ Laughing ]
-First time on TV?
Yeah, never really
done this before.
[ Laughter ]
-GUY: Get your pictures.