I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Holy moly!
...we're loading up
the spices...
Oh, that's great.
...and stacking up
the sandwiches.
Have to get a big breath.
You'll be down
for a while.
Like in Longmont, Colorado...
Let me see the magic,
homie.
...where pork turns
into a primo patty.
There's nothing I would
do different to that.
And in a brotherly joint
in Columbus, Ohio...
Aw, that's so good.
...piled on goodness,
Chicago‐style.
I don't have anything
I can say
other than, can
I have another one?
And in Los Angeles...
Ahh! Ahh!
[ Laughter ]
...a funky spot
firing up an Asian inferno.
It just ate the enamel
off my teeth.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins
&amp; Dives."
♪♪♪
So, I live in
northern California,
but I was born here
in Columbus, Ohio,
and I'm here
to check out a joint
that's owned by two Greek dudes
that are from Chicago.
Wait a second.
Did I confuse you yet?
Don't worry about it.
You looking for
some real‐deal gyro?
It's right here at Loops ‐‐
Just Good Food.
♪♪♪
We got two Po' Boys
going down!
Lots of flavor and just
good, authentic food.
We got four dogs
walking in right now.
It's up there with anything
you can find in Chicago.
FIERI: Because the whole thing
was dreamt up
by two Windy‐City transplants ‐‐
brothers Andrew
and Jim Constantinides
who were missing the flavors
of their hometown.
Growing up,
going downtown,
you'd find a place that had the
best chicken or the best gyro.
So, when we were
coming up with the menu,
we're like, "These are
the things we're gonna do."
"We'll take the best from this
one, the best from that one."
Exactly.
That's exactly right.
I got Italian beef, hot!
‐I love the Italian Beef.
‐It's amazing.
It stacks up with any
other beefs back in Chicago.
Let's talk about
breaking down Italian Beef.
We're gonna start
with our gravy.
So, we have broth
that's left over
from the last round
of roasting.
Then the onions.
Celery next, garlic, pepper.
We use a couple bay
leaves. Water.
How long is this gonna go?
Right around four hours.
Then we strain it
and go from there.
And this would be the jus
that's used to heat up the meat?
Right.
Next?
Trimmed eye of the round.
Correct.
Big piece of meat
to work with.
We have to make our dry rub.
We start with onion powder,
garlic powder,
oregano, basil, salt, and,
last but not least, pepper.
Okay.
Put the beef into
the pan with some stock.
Season the beef heavily.
Take another quart 'cause you
want some more juice in there
so as it's roasting,
it gives off that steam
that gives off a nice flavor.
So, we're going to roast
and steam this at the same time?
Exactly right.
Just a little
over medium rare?
over medium rare.
Bring it out, let it cool,
slice it thin?
Correct.
We toast our hoagie.
Now, that's not
a typical Chicago thing.
No, it's not.
We like to toast it
because it just adds
a little bit more flavor.
I'm with you.
It's elevating the program.
You take the beef, and you
just add into the au jus.
Just to warm it up.
And the idea is not to
stack it as one big clump.
You want a ribbon it
when it goes inside.
That's a good word.
I like that.
Layer it up. Oh...
Do you like yours dipped,
drowned, or dry?
I'll take it dipped.
Oh.
Next up is giardiniere
with the peppers.
Okay.
The question is,
you like hot or mild?
Oh, I'm hot.
This is the key ‐‐
it's this balance
between the meat,
the peppers,
the crunch, the vinegar.
There's your Italian Beef.
Okay.
So, the hunch
started from Philly,
but you have to use it
when you do an Italian Beef.
Have to get a big breath.
You'll be down for a while.
♪♪♪
Aw, that's so good.
The meat cut perfectly thin.
Light and delicate.
Almost gets the texture
of filet mignon.
Right amount of jus.
The bun doesn't die.
I think the toasting thing
is what everybody
in Chicago
should be learning from.
Great giardiniere.
I think that's a key to it.
That right there is exactly
what it tastes like in Chicago.
We're not in Chicago,
are we?
No.
I don't have anything
I can say other than,
can I have another one?
As many as you like.
The beef is perfect.
It is shaved thin,
wonderful, tender.
The giardiniere
is what makes it.
Oh, my goodness. It just
brings out all the flavor.
WOMAN: Andy and Jimmy are great.
They're always having
a good time.
Don't be checking me, Jimmy.
It's not hockey season yet.
MAN: There's nothing like coming
in here on a busy lunch rush
and the two of them
are going at it.
Come on, bro.
Gimme, gimme, gimme!
Coming, coming, man!
I'm not a magician.
Depends on our moods and if
we're in sync or if we're not.
Yeah. We'll start cursing
at each other in Greek.
‐In Greek?
‐Oh, yeah.
FIERI: Besides talking the talk,
they're also walking the walk
with this Greek classic.
Two Titans ‐‐ one with feta,
one with onions! Fry up!
Stacked pork, served gyro‐style
with the tzatziki,
lettuce, tomato, onion.
They season it up right,
and it's awesome.
This is a real, authentic,
Greek gyro
the way they do it
in Greece.
Pork only? Pork and beef?
We use strict
pork shoulder.
So, trim it up,
freeze it up, slice it thin?
We season it
and build the spit.
Let's see it.
We start with garlic powder,
basil, oregano,
paprika, onion powder, salt,
and, of course, some pepper.
Okay.
Mix it up,
spread it on top of the meat.
Another layer so it
gets the seasoning
from the top and the bottom.
Exactly.
Let this set overnight.
Let the flavors work
all the way through it.
Then we'll throw it
on the spit?
Correct.
What, do you get
your hoof on there
and you hold that
with one leg...
No.
...then you start stacking?
Somebody will hold this.
Somebody will slice it.
Somebody will stack it.
You have to interrupt somebody's
job to have them hold it?
Well, there are a lot
of overpaid people here,
so it's usually
not a problem.
Start stacking, homes.
Like I said,
overpaid people ‐‐
[ Laughter ]
I'm joking! I'm joking!
I'm joking!
♪♪♪
Alright, so, you load
this thing up.
But you got to have this.
Ah, that's the key.
[ Laughs ]
Throw it on the rotisserie,
and we'll make
some tzatziki?
Absolutely. Now, it's
a little bit different
because we don't use yogurt,
we use sour cream.
Cucumber.
But you ground it up?
Yes, we actually use just
the skin and the pulp.
Dill.
It's the real deal.
It's the real, dry dill.
Puree garlic.
We use pickle juice. Gives it
a little bit of a flair.
‐Okay.
‐A little red wine vinegar.
Salt, some olive oil.
Italian?
No, we don't use
inferior olive oil here.
[ Laughter ]
And a little bit of mayo.
We do let all the flavors
come out of it overnight.
I like to get
that cucumber flavor
without having to have
such big pieces in it.
Yeah.
Okay, let's go.
♪♪♪
What is that thing?
It's the most expensive
knife I've ever owned.
If you drop it, I fire you.
You don't have to worry
about dropping.
I'm gonna drop it in the
glove compartment of my car.
Dude, that is legit.
We start with the pita.
A little bit of meat.
Got to have a Greek tzatziki.
All the fat, everything
you love about a pork cut,
but, like, all of it's bark.
And there's your Titan.
I got to tell you something.
Honestly, bro,
I thought your pork
was cut a little thick.
By the time it cooks down
and renders, wow!
Incredible crust,
but tender.
And the tzatziki ‐‐
outstanding.
And a really good pita.
That's from Chicago, as well?
Yeah.
I might like that more
than the Italian Beef.
Don't ever come
eat one of these.
You will be disappointed
if you eat one
anywhere else after that.
There's your Titan.
Thanks, guys. Enjoy!
The meat's really good.
It's nice and flavorful.
Pita's nice and soft.
Is it the meat?
Is it the pita?
Man: It's the tzatziki.
Italian Beef, meatball sub,
Polish Po' Boy ‐‐ you are up!
‐It's just the perfect place.
‐You have to come here.
For people to be able
to cruise in here
and get all of this
experience, that's great.
So, thanks for having me.
Absolutely.
‐Thank you, man.
‐Appreciate it.
♪♪♪
FIERI: Up next, I'm bringing
reinforcements to Los Angeles...
Holy cow, is that good!
‐Oh!
‐...for a little fire...
It is gonna be so hot.
...and a whole lot of flavor.
This is one of the best Thai
experiences I've ever had.
♪♪♪
Man, the things
I get myself into.
I'm here in Los Angeles.
‐Actually, where exactly?
‐We're in Hollywood.
‐No, we're in Thai Town.
‐Wherever we are.
So, Aarti and Jet were judges
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
We had this crazy
chef named...
Jet: Jazz.
...that comes in
and rocks the house,
and I said, "If you win..."
"Then we have to go!"
And here we are.
This is Jitlada.
♪♪♪
Pla Pear, table one!
The best Thai food
in the country.
We have the Spicy Mint Noodles
with shrimp.
There's regular Thai food,
and there's Jitlada.
What is it about this place
that brings you back?
‐Jazz.
‐Jazz!
I think that's
the thing right there.
Jazz is known for
bringing the heat.
Something Jazz Singsanong
definitely showed us
on "Triple G,"
and she's bringing it here
every day after her brother,
Chef Tui Sungkamee, took over
this joint back in '06.
♪♪♪
‐You were a customer?
‐Yeah.
Before your brother
owned it?
Yeah. 1969.
It's been here
that long?
‐1969.
‐Seriously?
This used to be
a northern‐Thai restaurant,
and then they bought it,
and it became the best southern
Thai restaurant in America!
What is the basis
of southern Thai?
Less sweet, way more spicy.
Some of the items
are just super heat.
All the flavors that are in
Thai food are 100 times here.
Two Green Curries with chicken.
Easily the best green
curry I've ever had.
It's so good that
it's worth the burn.
Okay, so, what are
we gonna make?
We're gonna make Green Curry.
Let's see it.
♪♪♪
‐All of that?
‐Yes.
Mm, yeah.
♪♪♪
Yes.
Sri Lankan lime skin.
A little of the lime leaf.
Just, like, half of this
is green chilies.
‐Yeah, yeah.
‐I'm still, like...
Listen, it doesn't
have to be ‐‐
See, our Indian brothers
and sisters think
they can eat spicy.
We perfected the curry.
I'm gonna have to draw
back the curry curtain.
‐We perfected ‐‐
‐Somebody's gonna get
a hurting over here!
[ Ding! Ding! ]
♪♪♪
Seeds and everything.
So, this is raw, but for
the dish, it'll be cooked?
Yes, sir.
♪♪♪
I started to make
water mouth.
Salivate, yeah.
That's the word
I was looking for.
Up next?
‐Chicken.
‐Fish sauce?
‐Yeah.
‐The eggplant,
the bamboo shoots.
‐Smell it.
‐Sri Lankan lime leaf.
Bell pepper.
And then we do
the Thai basil.
More chilies?
[ Laughter ]
♪♪♪
Dude, wow.
Oh, my gosh.
One for you guys.
It is gonna be so hot.
Aw, dude, that's hot.
Oh, my God!
It just ate the enamel
off my teeth.
‐That's delicious.
‐But there's so much flavor.
‐It's not just spicy.
‐Do we have rice or anything?
‐Yes.
‐You pour it over the top?
‐Yeah, so, here.
‐Ooh, I want the eggplant.
The color is incredible.
This is what I really appreciate
about this ‐‐ it is hot,
but it's not unpleasantly hot
where it's destroying
your taste buds.
It's just this warm heat
throughout your face.
Yeah.
It's so alive where it's
just hitting every taste bud.
And the problem is I don't
want to stop eating.
‐I know.
‐I mean, that's it.
The crave‐ability
is through the roof.
So good, Jazz.
Green Curry chicken.
It's phenomenal.
The spices are nice and complex.
Once you try it, you really
can't put that spoon down.
Before she was here doing this,
nobody was doing southern Thai.
Yeah, it took a fan
to translate her
Thai menu into English
for this place to blow up.
Have you seen the menu?
It's like a bible.
There's probably
300 items on it.
Curry, duck, crab, frog legs.
It would take so long
to try everything,
but it's all really good.
We have to take
a little break.
The team and I
are gonna rest it off,
maybe go in the walk‐in,
but we're here at Jitlada.
When we come back,
the queen herself, Jazz,
will whip up another dish.
FIERI: And she won't be
dialing down the heat.
‐Tom Yum Shrimp.
‐Spicy.
It's got a kick.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
You put them all in there?!
Jet: Dude!
♪♪♪
Welcome back. "Triple D"
is here at Jitlada in Hollywood
with my great friends, Jet Tila,
super chef, and Aarti Sequeira,
curry sister
from another mister,
but most importantly,
Queen Jazz.
‐Oh, yeah.
‐Pose it! Could you...
[ Laughter ]
Not only can Jazz Singsanong
light up a room,
on "Guy's Grocery Games,"
she proved she's got the
culinary cred to back it up.
[ Laughter ]
When I tell you
how crazy this place is ‐‐
the food is out of bounds.
The best Thai food in LA.
It's definitely easy
to get addicted to.
Alright, my sister,
what are we making next?
‐Tom Yum seafood.
WOMAN: Really good take
on a classic dish.
Really good mushrooms, tomatoes.
‐Great mix of Thai flavors.
‐And a little Thai medicine.
What is this?
‐Yeah?
‐Like Ryan Gosling ‐‐
when he gets sick,
he never takes any medication.
Ryan Gosling is her boy.
I can't believe
it's taken this long.
He eats here.
Wait a sec. What did you
say about Ryan Gosling?
‐Ryan Gosling ‐‐
‐You like Ryan more than Guy?
Ahh! Ahh!
You better live close by
'cause you're walking home.
Let's make the dish.
The seafood broth, lemongrass.
‐Lemongrass. Galanga.
That kind of tastes
like cardamom.
Okay.
Then we're gonna
add some seafood.
Snapper, scallops, calamari,
green‐lipped mussels,
and a little bit of shrimp.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
[ Laughter ]
Dude, that's one order
of soup right there.
‐I know.
‐It's okay.
It's just flavor.
You know, not...
Yeah, just flavor.
[ Laughter ]
Lime juice.
‐Fish sauce?
‐Yeah.
Chili paste.
That's magic
right there, man.
‐Sugar.
‐How many is this normally
for ‐‐ 18 people?
For Guy only.
‐Yeah, Ryan Gosling only.
‐Ohh! Exactly!
Oh, man, look at that!
Ohh! That looks awesome.
♪♪♪
Oh, that's great.
‐Holy cow, is that good!
‐Ohh!
‐The citrus in there ‐‐
‐Yeah. It's so bright.
It's light broth,
but it's got such flavor.
FIERI: But the real kicker
is you got to get the fish.
Jet: Agreed.
Scallop.
The more we eat, the more
she fills it back up.
Okay, it's like the
never‐ending bowl over here.
I got spicy Tom Yum soup
and chicken for you, sir.
Excellent lemongrass flavor.
The broth has a surprising kick.
It's also really tangy.
There's plenty of great
Thai food in Los Angeles,
but this is still my favorite.
The next day,
you're already like,
"Wow, I could go back
and eat that again."
Jitlada has been a place
that people come over
and over and over again in LA.
It's like the jewel
in the crown.
This is one of the best
Thai experiences I've ever had.
You want a cultural experience?
You want true, southern Thai?
You make sure you come
visit this place.
‐It's amazing.
‐This is the queen right here.
‐Give it up for Jazz.
‐Yay, Jazz!
Coming up, in Longmont,
Colorado...
Love it.
...the neighborhood spot
with a righteous menu...
This thing's bangin'!
...and a heartfelt mission.
You're good dudes.
What do you think
of how old I am?
Uhh, 48?
[ Smooching ]
I'm 63! 63!
Rowr!
♪♪♪
You know, there's
a lot of things
that make up a great restaurant.
You got the location.
You got the attitude.
You got the personality.
Of course, you got to have
great food, but it's the people.
People really make up
a great part of this.
So, I'm here in Longmont,
Colorado,
to check out a joint where
two buddies decided
to open up a restaurant,
take some of the proceeds
to help other people,
and they serve great food.
That's my kind of place.
This is The Roost.
♪♪♪
Prime pork,
coming in 30 seconds.
‐Food's incredible.
‐Sliders up!
Cauliflower up!
The culture here
is like no other.
Because owner Dan Lance
is all about
creating community
and giving back.
I was doing a non‐profit
raising money for adoptions.
‐Really?
‐Yeah,
it wasn't
going well by myself.
So, he called buddy Sean Gafner,
who was cooking in California,
and pitched a crazy idea.
How about we design
something that's for profit
and use some of that
to fund adoption?
FIERI: Fast forward a few years,
and this place is jamming
thanks in part to a unique dish
quickly becoming
a local favorite.
‐Bangin' Cauliflower.
‐Bangin' Cauliflower is a must.
When you come in here and eat,
everyone has it on their table.
Nice and crunchy.
It's got a spicy sauce on it.
FIERI: Alright, what are
we making, boss?
So, we're making
the Bangin' sauce
for the Bangin' Cauliflower.
"Bangin'" as in,
"This thing's bangin'!"
It's bangin'.
Let me see the magic,
homie.
First, we bring some hoisin
and sweet chili together,
kind of meld the flavors.
Orange juice, lemon juice,
lime juice ‐‐ all fresh squeezed
'cause it's got
to taste like fruit.
Bring to a boil,
whisk it together.
Then, we strain it into
just the sriracha mayo.
So, a little fat
and a little heat.
We just put a
quarter cup into here.
Oh, just a touch?
Yeah, that's powerful.
That's a lot of
citrus and hoisin.
That's bangin'.
That'll definitely work.
Now onto cauliflower.
All the dry ingredients
we whisk together first.
Some rice flour, kosher salt,
fresh‐ground black pepper,
a little granulated garlic,
dark chili powder,
and some fresh‐ground
cumin seed.
Got it.
Whisk that together,
and then add in the water.
Alright. Dredge and fry?
Dredge and fry.
It's not very heavily
coated.
No, it's light.
And what are we frying it in?
Rice bran oil.
Rice bran oil?
Yeah.
I like it.
360.
Crispy cauliflower.
And it gets bangin'.
Now we top with
some fresh scallion.
♪♪♪
I'll tell you what ‐‐ you can't
call something "bangin'"
unless it tastes
like that.
Thank you.
That's legit.
The rice flour's the kicker.
Any other batter would've
burned up on you.
It adds a little
bit of crunch.
You still get cauliflower.
The acid in the sauce
countering the fry
and the sweet with
the fat of the mayo
and the punch
of the sriracha
is all just done
in this little micro‐balance
just the right way.
That's one of the most
simplistic recipes
I've ever seen on "Triple D,"
and it's dynamite.
Awesome job.
And the Bangin' Cauliflower.
Enjoy.
It has a great kick,
but it's refreshing and cool.
I know that when
I bring my kids here,
they will eat
their vegetables.
Every time you come,
you got to get them.
Steak Frites, coming over!
The Roost was exactly
what Longmont needed.
Cool bar. The rooftop patio ‐‐
it brings so much to
the community and downtown.
All their food is local ‐‐
local beef, local pork.
Plating
Perfect Pork Burgers.
The pork burger
is phenomenal.
It is so delicious. I have
tasted nothing like it before.
Just an awesome dish.
Alright, chef.
We are making the Perfect
Pork Burger patties.
First, you got to sauté
the aromatics in sesame oil.
Okay.
Fresh garlic,
fresh‐ground ginger.
You don't want to
over‐caramelize
'cause those are
delicate ingredients.
I gotcha.
Chili sambal.
Deglaze with soy sauce.
Let it cool down a little bit.
Okay.
So, this is my buddy
Clint's pork
he raises right here
in Longmont.
What's Clint's ranch called?
Buckner Family Farms.
He's raising the pork,
has it butchered,
has it ground, and you get it?
That's right.
Love it.
You add in the
aromatics, scallion,
cilantro,
fresh basil, kosher salt...
And fresh‐ground
black pepper.
...fresh‐ground
Like that.
And you just make
a perfect patty.
How are we gonna prepare
this Perfect Pork patty?
We're gonna push
the Perfect Pork patty
into the perfect ring mold.
Now we take it over to
the planch and make it perfect.
[ Laughter ]
Now we make kimchi.
Napa cab.
I love Napa cabbage because
the texture is perfect.
So, we take that,
start salting?
Sure.
Draw out all that extra
moisture, and then some water.
Mix it up, cover with plastic,
room temp, at least 12 hours.
Here's the Napa cabbage.
We've strained off
the excess water.
Fish sauce, sambal,
green parts of scallion,
fresh ginger...
Holy moly!
...fresh garlic,
a little sugar.
Three weeks in the walk‐in?
That's right.
And that's the mount
for this perfect pork patty.
Yeah.
So, these buns are from the
bread ladies across the street.
Got it.
The Bangin' sauce.
Oh, really? Bangin' sauce
makes another appearance?
Some of our kimchi
on the bottom.
Perfect Pork patty.
Lot of pressure when
you call it "perfect."
Blistered shishitos just tossed
in a little salt and lime.
My buddy Mark also grows
these here in Longmont.
I'm down with
the shishito move.
Top it with the brioche bun.
Perfect.
♪♪♪
I don't use
the word "perfect."
It's just too much
of an ultimate term.
It's like "always"
and "never."
The way I would describe this
is there is nothing
I would do different to that.
The little touch
of the shishito, the acid,
the tang, the funk
of the kimchi,
you allow the pork
to have some flavor.
You didn't put too much
into it.
The patty itself
is really juicy.
Bangin' sauce should be
available by the gallon,
and I hear that you guys
typically put an egg on it.
I'm not a super‐big egg fan,
so I appreciate you
keeping it ‐‐ but this
right here with an egg
would put it up
into that "pretty
righteous" category.
Using that "P" word
you like to use.
It's pretty dynamite.
I mean, it really is.
I've got the
Perfect Pork Burger.
The patty has this ginger,
basil explosion.
The shishito gives
a nice kick to it.
It's cooked to perfection.
I love coming here.
It's fresh food all the time.
It's delicious.
I love the vibe.
It's just a fun place to be.
You're good dudes.
I applaud what you're doing
and how you're helping others,
and all that love and all
that appreciation of food
comes out in what you make.
‐Thanks, man.
‐Awesome.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins, &amp; Dives."
‐Perfectly cooked.
‐Anything else?
It's perfectly moist.
Perfectly blistered
shishito right there, too.
Where's your wife?
Please manage him.
[ Laughter ]