I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
...it's a journey
across the Pacific
without ever
leaving the States.
Oh, my Gosh!
We've got off-the-chain
Chinese in Kansas City.
Fantastic.
Yes.
A killer Korean coffee shop
in San Fran.
Nailed it!
Top-notch Thai
in Oregon and Arizona.
You got to come check it out.
And from New York and Utah...
Out of bounds.
...Vietnamese specialties
that will blow your mind.
I could eat this thing
till my head falls off.
So, get read for this full hour
of amazing Asian.
This is my kind of food.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
I'm here in Ridgewood, Queens.
Now, I'm about, let me think,
about 1,000 miles away
from downtown Manhattan.
Actually,
I'm only five miles away,
but it seems like
I'm way out here.
I mean, I'm in
this industrial park.
We've got a scrap metal joint
there,
we've got a concrete plant
over here.
You're saying, "Guy,
why are you so far out?"
Listen, I hear they got a joint
with the bomb Vietnamese food.
This is Bun-ker.
♪♪
Shrimp going out.
It's in the middle of nowhere.
And the food, it just hits
my heart, you know. I love it.
Here's your traditional
banh xeo.
It's like you're eating
in Vietnam.
FIERI:
Central Vietnam, to be exact,
where chef Jimmy Tu's
mom and dad were raised.
Cha ca going out.
In 2013, he took
what his mama had taught him
and tricked out a menu loaded
with Vietnamese street food.
We got about five minutes
on these pork chops.
The grilled pork chops here
are absolutely incredible.
It is my favorite.
All right,
so what are we gonna make?
A marinade for
the suon nuong xa.
Suon nuong xa.
Yeah.
Lemongrass grilled pork.
Okay.
We got garlic,
tired chili peppers.
Okay.
Lemongrass.
Shallots.
And this is all
just for the marinade?
Yeah.
And we're gonna
put it in here
and hit it with
the mortar and pestle.
Yeah.
So, breaking this down.
So this is really opening it up,
bringing all that flavor out.
Now we're gonna put it
in a bowl.
And to this,
we're gonna add sea salt.
Sugar.
Fish sauce.
Canola oil.
And this is
a Chinese XO sauce.
It's like
a Chinese barbecue sauce.
Stir that up.
♪♪
You could marinate
a seat cushion,
and that
would taste great.
[ Chuckles ]
I'll cut the pork loin.
This is a Berkshire pork loin.
Got to use
good ingredients.
Gorgeous.
Yeah.
All right, so right in here
to the marinade?
Yeah.
Mix it in there.
Seven to eight hours.
Yeah. Killer.
Marinated pork chops go on the
grill for about five minutes.
Now you can see all the fibers
of that lemongrass
sticking to the pork.
[ Sizzling ]
♪♪
Plate this pork chop
right here.
Scallion oil.
♪♪
Crispy pork skin.
And...
the egg right here.
Don't pop that yolk.
♪♪
Out of bounds!
This is tender,
super flavorful.
Mmm!
Juicy.
Rich.
Let me get in
some of these pickled veg.
A little garlic.
That really is,
without question,
one of the best pork chops
I've ever had.
Mmm!
I could eat this thing
till my head falls off.
Here's your suon nuong xa.
A little bit crunchy
on the outside,
tender on the inside,
and seasoned perfectly.
The runny egg on the top, it
slices through it like butter.
Oh, my God, just delicious.
Mmm!
Beef going out.
It's the type of food
that you come here and you eat,
and you're thinking about it
all week.
FIERI:
It's that kind of obsession
that makes this place
a pilgrimage worth making.
I like it for the quaint
view of the scrap metal.
What was here before you?
When we started here,
we were doing a boutique
seafood distribution.
Okay.
Hence the weird location.
But then Sandy hit us,
we got flooded, we --
Here?
Yeah. It was a mess.
Really?
Yeah, yeah.
So you came in,
you built this out.
I always wanted to do, you know,
Vietnamese street food.
So while the flooded building
became the inspiration
for the name,
the menu is pure comfort.
We're talking lemongrass
short ribs, caramelized shrimp,
or this dish, that comes with
a fanatical following.
The crispy crepe
changed my life.
What's the first thing
we're gonna make?
Our banh xeo batter.
Fire it up.
We got rice flour.
Turmeric.
Sea salt.
Water.
It's very simple.
♪♪
Once that's nicely mixed,
add our scallions.
♪♪
That's it?
That's it.
Get this pan hot,
add a little oil.
This is Heritage bacon
that's smoked.
Combine it
with the shrimp.
I like that you're
cooking hot, dude.
Now we add the batter.
Nuts.
That rice flour falls underneath
the oil in the bacon fat,
and it's just soaking it up
at the same time.
Whoa.
Easy on the egg.
Trying to cut that.
There you go. That's plenty.
We add some bean spouts.
This looks good.
Fold it over.
Never seen anything
like this.
Drain this off.
♪♪
And this is how it gets served,
on the bamboo board?
Yeah.
Okay, so I load it up
like this.
Yeah.
Grab whatever herbs you want.
A little basil,
a little mint.
Yeah.
Wrap it up.
Dip it like this?
Yep.
Mmm!
That is nuts!
Dude, oh, my gosh!
I don't know how to
break this down...
about what is
more fantastic.
This right here with the bacon
and the scallions
and the crispiness
and the shrimp...
...that is wicked good,
dude.
Mmm!
Banh xeo going out.
It's crispy,
but it's also soft.
It's all melty.
The freshness of
the bean sprouts,
the savoriness of the bacon
and the shrimp.
Bun-ker food has probably
the best aspects
of every Southeast Asian
cooking cuisine out there.
I think if there was a last meal
on Earth,
I'm gonna have it
right here.
Mmm!
I've eaten great food, but this,
without question, is dynamite.
Excellent job.
Thank you, man.
FIERI: Coming up, it's a sibling
showdown in Kansas City...
You're as crazy
as your sister.
...where cooking up
lights-out Chinese...
Ooh!
All right.
That's when
the magic happens.
Yeah.
...is only part of the fun.
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
fry, fry, fry! ♪
There you go.
Come on down for the musical.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Kansas City, Missouri.
Now, I can almost promise you
I've been in this neighborhood
before.
Bookstore looks super familiar.
And if I'm right,
take a look at this.
Right there.
that was Bell Street Mama's,
a joint that we shot
in season three,
and then they moved
to a larger location.
I mean, to think the place
I'm about to visit
was here
at the same time I shot it.
I could have double-dipped,
I could have shot both!
Oh!
I'm not gonna miss it this time.
This is Blue Koi.
♪♪
It is traditional Chinese,
but it's a bit of a twist.
Firebird chicken is ready!
It's not Kung Pao chicken.
It's not General Tso's chicken.
It's just
a whole different game,
whole different kind of food.
How you doing there,
Jane?
FIERI: 'Cause the Chang siblings
are serving up
Chinese family recipes
mixed with big-time personality.
Chicken lettuce wrap!
Got it, got it!
From brother Scott
working the front of the house
to sisters Jane and Mindy
cooking in the back.
Two orders chili pepper wontons
here.
Okay, got it!
Who's a better cook,
you or your sister?
Of course, my sister.
She's right over there.
We'll stick with Mindy for now,
'cause she's cooking up
one of my all-time favorites.
Chili pepper wonton!
It's fabulous.
It's the perfect meal.
It's awesome, it's bomb.
It's bomb?
It's bomb, yeah.
I need soy sauce, vinegar.
Rice wine vinegar,
or is it regular vinegar?
This is regular vinegar.
Okay.
Yeah.
Sesame oil.
White pepper.
Sugar.
Garlic?
Garlic, yes.
Cilantro.
Cilantro -- lots of that.
They say you like cilantro.
We chop extra for you.
Green onion
and a homemade hot oil.
And we'll just stir.
Okay.
And that's all she wrote?
Mm-hmm.
Fantastic.
Yes.
[ Whistles ]
Next, we're gonna make
chili pepper wonton
filling.
Okay.
Okay?
Ground pork.
Ground pork,
ground chicken,
and chopped shrimp.
I like it.
A little
of the soy sauce.
Rice wine, sesame oil,
white pepper.
Green onion.
Okay, we'll just mix them
really well.
Okay.
Yeah.
And then
we're gonna let it sit
for, mm, 10, 20 minutes,
just let it all marinate
together.
Marinate a little bit,
okay.
Next?
We're gonna make
the chili pepper wonton.
There we go.
And we'll just kind of
seal the two sides.
Seal the deal, got it.
And so, then that way,
the meat won't fall out.
Yeah.
Okay, and then put a little bit
on the side here.
There we go. And...
And just fold it.
Ooh!
All right.
That's when
the magic happens.
Yeah.
How many come from --
What are you doing?
You know how many I make
of these at home.
I know.
I just want to see it, you know,
with my own eyes.
You want to see it
with your own eyes?
Yeah.
Okay.
I don't think mine
look right.
Exactly.
No, it's good.
Is that right?
Yep.
Okay, so now we're gonna
pan-fry these?
Yep.
And I like them crispy.
All right, then we'll just
make it extra for you.
♪♪
We ready to go?
Yep, mm-hmm.
Okay.
Nice and crispy for you.
There you go.
And we're gonna put
this awesome sauce in there.
♪♪
There you go.
Mmm! I love the vinegar smell
in that.
[ Blows ]
A little sweet,
a little heat.
Mmm!
These are awesome.
This dipping sauce
is ridiculous.
As everybody at home knows,
I'm a huge Chinese food fan.
So just for scientific purposes,
I'm gonna have eight more.
Awesome job.
Yes.
Winner, winner, chili pepper
wonton for dinner...
at Blue Koi.
Yeah!
They're incredible.
Quite a nice kick.
So, what do you think
makes the food so great?
Love.
Love, for sure.
MAN:
They've really become, like, the
family that I have in the city.
There's no hello, good-bye, it's
just like I never really left.
Now, this is Jane,
and I cooked with Mindy.
But, now,
Jane's Mindy's sister,
they share the same birthday
but different year.
Did I get that right?
That's correct.
I'm so confused.
So, Jane,
what are we gonna make?
Okay, we're going to make the
Firebird chicken on noodles.
Firebird chicken's ready.
Firebird chicken is my favorite.
Really good stuff.
You get a little bit spicy,
you get some sweet.
It's stuff you can't get
other places in town.
I love it.
Firebird chicken.
Right. We need to marinate
the chicken first.
Marinate the chicken.
Yes.
Got it.
Sliced chicken breast.
And then we need to add
a little bit of water into it,
because you need to
massage them --
Massage the chicken.
Until all the water
go in the chicken.
And then we add
some corn starch into it
so the moisture,
it will be holding into it.
♪ Massage, massage, massage,
you know? ♪
Is that a massage song
you're singing?
Yeah, yeah,
to the chicken.
And they are happy, so my
customer, they are very happy.
You know,
that's how we cook.
You're as crazy
as your sister.
[ Laughs ]
And then little bit
of ginger onion oil
we make in the house.
And then, that way,
when you cook,
they'll not stick together.
Got it.
[ Sizzling ]
Gonna brown it both sides?
Brown it both sides.
And then I put the noodles
in the water.
That you make
here in-house.
We make in the house.
So we'll add some sizzling
in there.
We'll put garlic,
the rice wine.
Here comes fire!
And we have the sugar.
Soy sauce,
Chinese barbecue sauce.
Now it's red pepper.
That you make
here in-house.
We make in the house --
red chili.
A little bit of chicken broth
into it.
We put bamboo shoots
in there.
And the green onions.
♪♪
Our chicken's ready, noodles
ready, we're ready to plate.
So we'll put a little bit of
our house-made ginger onion oil
and a little bit of soy sauce
into the bowl
and pick up the noodles.
You see what I'm saying?
Look at that.
You don't see that everywhere.
And we toss them.
♪♪
Firebird is ready.
Going to be fire.
It's spicy.
Very spicy.
Fire -- that's why
it's called Firebird.
Fire!
♪ Too hot, too hot ♪
Another song.
♪ Ah, ha ha ha ♪
Oh, oh!
Kidding.
Mmm!
There's some heat,
no question.
The noodle is awesome.
Nice texture to it,
al dente.
Everything you want --
a little spice...
a little fresh veg,
great texture of the noodle,
super-tender chicken.
Not typical Chinese food.
You got to come try it.
It's just so good.
It's kind of got this smoky,
like, Asian barbecue flavor.
I've been coming here
about nine years.
I come like three days a week.
It's like eating
in someone's kitchen.
Firebird chicken!
Jane, that looks wonderful!
It's just amazing comfort food.
Nice job.
Yes!
You got a song for me?
Goes...
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
fry, fry, fry! ♪
There you go.
Come on down for the musical.
FIERI:
Up next, a funky walk-up spot
in Portland, Oregon...
Ain't not a thing
but a chicken wing.
...dishing out
real-deal Thai...
What a dish.
...that's way too good
to be shared.
Nope.
[ Laughs ]
Not today.
♪♪
I'm here in Portland, Oregon,
where you can always expect
a little rain
and a lot of great food.
I'm here
to check out this joint,
it's called Pok Pok,
where they don't
let a little rain
keep them from making
some killer Thai food.
You know, I think we need
to start calling the show
"Diners, Drive-ins
& Walk-ups."
Two orders of the kai yaang.
I've never had food like this
before, but it's really tasty.
It's really authentic.
That's why we're here.
Everything on the menu has been
something I've either eaten
or eaten and cooked
in another country
and then
brought it back here.
FIERI:
To serve up to Andy Ricker's
growing crowd
of Portland fans.
Justin?
We opened as just this shack
right here,
and from there,
it just grew.
Into the house next door
and a barbecue pit
in the back.
We keep that fire hot.
I've been doing my best
to get people
to try something new
and different.
I'm having the boar collar.
FIERI: Yep, boar meat,
marinated, grilled,
and served
in a chili lime garlic sauce.
They said it was
the spiciest thing on the menu,
and it's delicious.
We're making
muu paa kham waan,
which is boar collar --
the neck meat from the boar.
Why the neck?
It's got a lot of flavor,
and the Thai people
really like it as a cut.
And then we're gonna make
the paste that you rub it with.
So, this mortar and pestle is
granite and comes from Thailand.
We're doing cilantro root.
Cilantro root?
Yeah.
Garlic, a little bit of salt,
some black pepper.
Now, why not
a food processor?
There's something
that happens
when you pound it
than if you cut it.
And it's really the traditional
way of doing things in Thailand.
Now, we're just gonna
take this paste
and just kind of
work it into the meat.
I love it.
Then we're just gonna take
a little seasoning sauce,
which is essentially
soy sauce.
But lighter.
And then we're gonna add a
little bit of super-fine sugar.
Breaks down
quickly and evenly.
Typically, we let it marinate
for a couple hours
before we grill it.
Now we're gonna make
the sauce.
So we're just gonna take
the chilies, garlic,
dump them in the Robot Coupe,
pulse that up a little bit
so it's not completely
broken down,
but got those flavors
combining.
Then the lime juice,
a little bit of orange juice,
fish sauce,
and the sugar.
This is the counterbalance?
It balances out sour
and salty.
Finally, the cilantro.
So this has all the Thai --
hot, sour, salty, sweet.
Whoo! Oh!
Now it's gonna go
on the grill.
Regular old charcoal?
Natural hardwood charcoal.
Okay. What do you do when
it rains heavy out here?
Uh...
Get wet?
We just get wet.
It's Oregon, man.
How we looking?
We should be around medium,
medium-rare there.
Pull that off. Then we're
just gonna slice it up,
pile it on the plate, and we're
gonna hit it with the sauce.
A little bit of cilantro
for it.
And then we got
the iced mustard greens.
You take a little sticky rice,
and then you can use that
to pick up some of the meat
and the sauce
and pop that
in your mouth.
Mmm!
And just take a little iced
crispy yu choy to eat with it.
This is ridiculously good.
Crunchy, spicy,
sugar, salty.
Northern Thai
drinking food.
Looks good, huh,
hungry camera?
Nope.
[ Laughs ]
Not today.
It's really, really good.
Boar in the window.
Salty, spicy --
just right.
Coming up with the boar.
Super authentic, nothing that
you would just find anywhere.
Cha ca is in your window.
Here's satay.
It's O.G. It's awesome.
O.T. -- original Thailand.
FIERI:
Right down to the hardware.
This is a coconut milk press
that I brought back
from Thailand.
We're putting in
the fresh grated coconut,
mixing it with warm water.
There's a filter, and it presses
out the coconut milk.
All for only one dish --
the coconut curry soup.
Khao soi.
MAN: Totally authentic.
That's the way we had it in
the northern part of Thailand.
Khao soi is coming up.
We also like
the kung op wun sen --
the pork belly and the prawns.
Oh, he's going right
for the pork belly.
Well, I mean, come on.
That's crazy!
Flavor is just so intense.
But not spicy.
Not all Thai food is spicy.
Excellent dish.
Thank you.
Everything.
Got three kung op
ready to go.
Food's definitely delicious.
Cuttlefish coming in.
It was worth the wait
to get in here tonight.
McGinnis?
FIERI: Or you could just head
for the take-out window.
Hi, there.
Hi, guys.
We started with just this menu
that's right here.
That was it?
A handful of items.
The papaya pok pok.
FIERI: Including the one
this joint's named after.
Green papaya salad,
or papaya pok pok.
Pok pok is an onomatopoeia,
it's this noise right here.
Start out with a little bit of
garlic, a couple of chilies.
You like it spicy?
I'll take it spicy.
We'll make it
three chilies.
Nice big scoop
of palm sugar,
and we're gonna start
pounding that down.
That's pok pok. Okay.
That's pok pok.
Next, the fresh limes
with the skin and juice.
Garlic, lime,
and chili mojito going.
That's pretty much it.
Fried shrimp.
And then I'm gonna follow that
with some long beans.
All right, then some lime juice.
The ubiquitous fish sauce.
And this is tamarind water.
Gives a nice sour,
fruity flavor to it.
And now the green papaya.
This is all grated fresh
each time?
Grated fresh.
Then we're gonna start
pounding it all together here.
The dressing gets kind of
pushed into the green papaya,
but the green papaya
stays nice and crunchy.
Nice handful of cherry tomatoes,
and add some peanuts.
And each time,
this is the routine?
This is the way we do it
every time.
Man, someone's got to be
working hard at this job.
The next thing we're gonna do
is plate it up.
And then you got to eat this
with sticky rice.
Mmm! Wow.
You get all the flavors,
the crunch, the presentation.
Everybody's playing nice-nice.
There's no lead guitar in this.
This embodies the idea
of hot, sour, salty, sweet
more than anything else.
Mmm!
Awesome, dude.
Really, awesome.
It's a really great blend
of spicy and sour.
It's really tangy.
Papaya pok pok.
This is one of
my favorite dishes.
It's really exquisite.
This is khao soi gai.
Everything
is so uniquely different.
Whole bird.
It's not just
from one region.
FIERI: Or one country.
Wings!
The biggest hit on this menu
is Vietnamese.
Vietnamese chicken wings.
Spicy wings up.
My friends and I
like to call it meat candy.
Ain't not a thing
but a chicken wing.
That's right.
We've got some chopped garlic,
some salt.
Kind of massage
that together,
pulling the liquid
out of the garlic.
Add some water to it.
We're gonna use a cheese cloth.
Pour that in there
and squeeze it.
And that will flavor
the wings
without putting garlic
on the wings.
Because it will burn --
It will burn when you fry it.
To this,
we're gonna add sugar.
Super fine.
And fish sauce.
And then we're gonna go ahead
and mix that all,
and then we're just gonna
throw that marinade
on the chicken wings.
We'll give it
a darn good mixing.
You got not just
a marination going,
you got
a little osmosis going.
We got a bring going.
How long
will these marinate?
Overnight.
And then
we deep-fry them.
Yeah.
And then we're gonna toss it
in the wing caramel,
which is fish sauce,
some good, clean
Oregon tap water,
and a whole bunch
of sugar.
Real simple.
All right,
that's all mixed.
Now, wings, drained them,
dried them.
Now we're gonna mix
the wing dust, we call it.
Plain old Thai
jasmine rice flour.
Rice flour is so super fine
that it doesn't clump up on it.
And then
we got tempura mix.
We're gonna get some wings in
there and mix that all together.
It's just funny, 'cause
I'm not typically a fan
of a dredged wing,
but since it's such
a fine flour, I'll try it.
And then we're gonna drop it
right in the deep fryer,
and we're gonna start heating
that caramel base we just made.
When it starts bubbling --
You want it spicy?
Yeah, throw a little heat
on it.
Some of this chili paste
here.
That's gonna give it that
nice toasty spice flavor.
I pull those wings out.
Just gonna toss it
right in there.
And we're gonna throw in
our fried garlic.
Wow, you can see that candy
right on there.
We're just gonna do
a little trick here --
shvitz it with
just a touch of water.
It pulls the stuff off the side
of the pan in a nice glaze.
We'll let those cool
a little bit.
Cool lettuce to go with
the hot spicy wings.
Hot and spicy --
did you get that part?
Pickled daikon and cucumbers,
carrots.
Cilantro
to crunch up with it.
To cool down.
There you go.
Hot.
Mmm!
Let me tell you something,
that sauce
on the outside of that,
with that tempura flour,
makes it.
Mmm! Crunchy, tender,
falls off the bone.
What a dish.
They just never disappoint.
Wings up.
They're really sweet
and crispy and caramelized.
Wings down.
I get the wings every time.
How many of these have you
put away in your lifetime?
Probably more than
you've had hot meals.
[ Laughs ]
We love it.
Kung op ready to go.
One of the best meals in town.
Two orders of satay.
It's just very different. You're
not gonna find pad Thai here.
We don't sell pad Thai
at all.
Give me some.
No pad Thai.
That's what
I'm talking about.
You know
you're going gangster
when you don't take
the signature item
of the type of food
and put it on your menu.
FIERI: Coming up on this
full hour of amazing Asian...
I like this.
...in Holiday, Utah,
unforgettable pho...
I wish I could get in it.
...and the bomb banh mi.
That is unbelievable!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Getting sign-off
from a true sandwich specialist.
It's one of the best
hot sandwiches I've
ever had in my life.
It's incredible.
♪♪
So I'm here in Holiday, Utah,
about 10 minutes southeast
of Salt Lake,
to check out a joint that I hear
is doing the rocking
banh mi sandwich.
And to make sure it's rocking,
I brought this cat --
my buddy Jimmy John Liautaud
from Jimmy John's Sandwiches
to qualify it.
This is Oh Mai.
Oh Mai!
♪♪
Brisket pho ready to go.
This place is amazing.
Layers of flavor.
It's almost like
traveling to Vietnam.
WOMAN: The food at this place
is just as good
as the people
that own the place.
FIERI:
That would be Vietnamese-born
husband and wife team
of Long and Anna Tran,
two veterans of
the Salt Lake restaurant scene
looking to switch it up a bit.
We finally decided
to retire,
so that's why we bought
this little space.
You retired and did this?
Yes.
I guess retirement means serving
up righteous family recipes.
Everything here is fantastic.
FIERI:
Since I got my boy Jimmy John
rolling with me,
you know I got to start off
with a standout sandwich.
Banh mi.
The sandwich is just amazing.
FIERI: Let's talk about
what we're gonna make.
We're gonna make the pickled
carrots and daikon.
That go on the sandwich
to give it all the crunch?
Yes.
Everything sound good to you
so far?
Sounds good.
♪♪
Wow, what a machine.
Okay.
Now, are we ready?
Carrots, daikon.
And you want them
long ways?
Yeah, long way, please.
Fire it up.
So now
we have to marinate them.
Okay.
First, vinegar, sugar.
And...
Water.
How long will it take
until these pickle?
About two days.
And now this is the rib eye
that goes for the sandwich?
Correct.
And then you put in the butter
and let it melt a little bit.
And then
onions and garlic.
Okay.
And just sauté it
just a little bit.
And then you start
adding the rib eye.
Oh, that looks delicious.
Now, do you do this
for every sandwich fresh?
Yes, we cook to order.
It's beautiful.
Soy sauce, sugar.
And then black pepper.
So our meat's
about medium-rare?
Medium-rare
to medium cooked.
Okay, now we're ready
to go make the sandwich?
So what I do
is cut it out.
With scissors?
Yes.
And then
we hollow this out.
Who taught you
how to do that?
Me.
It's critical.
We call it canoeing.
Just the garlic butter
and then mayo.
And then romaine lettuce.
And then the rib eye meat.
And then black vinaigrette
house sauce, black pepper.
Cucumber.
[ Whistles ]
Tomato.
That looks good.
Red onion.
Jalapeño pepper.
Oh, I like the jalapeño.
Carrots and daikon.
And cilantro.
It's an Asian
Philly steak.
It is
an Asian Philly steak!
And that's all she wrote.
Here we go.
That is unbelievable!
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
[ Laughs ]
What do you get, Jimmy?
What are your flavors?
I'm getting the fresh-cooked
rib eye steak
and the sweet vinaigrette.
I love the cilantro.
And the jalapeño kicker
is just off the chart.
You got sweet, you got spicy,
you got salty,
you got fatty,
you got crunchy, you got --
I mean, you've got the whole
umami going on, and...
But my favorite part...
without question...
the carrot and the daikon.
It's one of the best
hot sandwiches I've
ever had in my life.
It's incredible.
It's like an explosion
of flavors.
Crunchy, crusty --
just awesome.
Listen, I know
you got to bounce.
Happy skiing to ya.
Thank you very much.
I had to bring
the sandwich man himself in.
Yeah.
Okay?
So nice to meet you.
What a treat this was for me.
You're the best.
Thank you, Jimmy.
I love the food so much,
I can eat it every day.
Brisket pho is ready!
Spelled P-H-O with an accent
across the top of it.
Yes, uh-huh.
But it is pronounced "fa."
Yes, correct.
Okay.
So, don't fa-get it.
Don't fa-get it.
Sorry, I had to.
So the bone --
this is beef bones.
Yes, correct,
beef bones.
So we're gonna cook off
the beef bones first.
Mm-hmm.
Here,
you want some help?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Strong hand.
Next, we're gonna put
the brisket into the pot.
This will cook for
about three hours.
You'll see, like, a little bit
of a foam coming to the top,
and we'll skim that off
as it goes, to get it as pure --
the broth --
it will be as clear as possible.
Yes, correct.
Okay.
While that is being cooked,
then we can start
roasting the spices.
A little cinnamon.
Okay, cinnamon,
star anise, edimum.
Edimum?
Yes.
I got to see what this is.
It comes from
the cardamom family.
Okay, so we're gonna toast these
about five minutes.
Take out
the cooked brisket.
Now we add the spice in?
Yes.
Look at that.
I've made some satchels before,
but that's ridiculous.
[ Whistles ]
And how long are we gonna
steep that in there?
For about six more hours.
Wow!
And then we're gonna
put this in while...
While that's simmering?
Yes.
So we've got the roasted ginger
and onions.
I like this.
And then...
Crystallized rock sugar.
Yes.
Am I doing good?
You're doing perfect.
And a little bit of salt.
And salt, yep.
So, after we get done simmering
this for six hours...
We're just gonna just
take out the bone
and whatever's in there,
and then, just the broth
is ready to go.
I want a taste of this.
♪♪
Oh, my gosh! Oh!
So now we're ready
for the noodles.
♪♪
And you just
pour the noodles in.
So that rice noodle
went really fast.
And then you put in the brisket,
put in the broth.
Oh!
And you just garnish it
with green onions,
cilantro,
and red onions.
And, last, but not least,
the black pepper.
A little Thai basil
on mine.
See, I have my method.
I'm Thai basil, jalapeños...
bean sprouts, for sure,
and a little bit of lime.
And a touch of sriracha.
There we go.
Now!
♪♪
Mmm!
The broth is outrageous.
The brisket's sliced
nice and thin.
Mmm!
In my world of pho,
this is one of the best.
Thank you.
I wish I could get in it.
Okay.
♪♪
Just so much flavor
and so much depth.
MAN: It tastes super fresh.
You can taste all
the ingredients that go into it.
I love squeezing the lime in it.
It's kind of the icing
on the cake, for me.
Out of bounds!
I'll finish the soup.
You can go.
[ Laughs ]
You can leave now.
FIERI:
Up next, don't be fooled by this
San Francisco coffee shop...
Okay?
[ Whistles ]
...'cause hiding inside...
This is the oddest burrito
I've ever seen.
...is a mouthwatering
Korean twist.
This seriously is some of the
stuff I love more than anything.
You got to dig "Triple D"
in Northern California,
especially when I'm just
three blocks from AT&T Park
where the San Francisco Giants
play.
Now, I cruise through this area
quite a bit,
and this funky little joint
didn't come up on my radar.
It's a coffee shop.
A coffee shop's what you call
a diner on the west coast.
But not just any coffee shop.
It's one that's spiked
with Asian fusion.
This is HRD Coffee Shop.
Sweet chili
fried pork chops.
I love the food here.
Mongolian cheese steak.
It's one of the greatest things
I've ever had.
Spicy pork tacos --
It's a crazy mixture.
WOMAN: Barbecue pork
scrambled eggs.
Asian-fusion American diner.
Sloppy Jojo!
How can they do that?
FIERI: Easily.
All right, there you go.
I'm Chinese.
You're Chinese.
Jojo is Korean.
Hey, how are you?
FIERI:
That would be Jojo Banks...
Put a bit more
spicy sauce.
...who partnered up
with her pal David Yeung...
How long is the line?
...when he decided to buy
his uncle's coffee shop.
We wanted to make a menu
that kind of combined
all the flavors
that we liked to eat.
What do people say
when they walk in
and then find
kimchee fried rice burrito?
They just scratch their heads
like you do.
Spicy pork kimchee burrito.
FIERI: Oh, yeah.
They also order it.
Korean barbecue in a burrito --
two best foods smashed together.
And then can put kimchi on
anything, and it's just awesome.
Kimchi into a burrito.
Yes.
First thing we do is
we take Napa cabbage.
Cut it in quarters?
Cut it in quarters.
After this,
Korean sea salt.
So this will pull
all the moisture out.
How long is this gonna sit
with the salt on it?
Overnight. We rinse it
and then make a sauce for it.
Give it to me.
A sweet rice flour.
Sweet rice powder.
We're gonna put a little water
in there.
Now we mix it up. This is just
kind of the binding agent?
Binding agent.
Red crushed pepper.
All of that?
All of that, okay?
[ Whistles ]
Korean anchovies.
Anchovy sauce.
We got some sugar.
Get the nice paste
in there.
Leeks?
Yep, julienned leeks.
Sliced daikon.
And then
we got some carrots.
You smell the flavors coming off
of that, how pungent it is?
Yeah, I do.
It's seriously some of the stuff
I love more than anything.
Rub everything inside
really, really well.
Put this in here.
Let it ferment.
And how long does the kimchi
ferment?
A day.
All right,
what are we gonna make?
Korean spicy pork sauce.
Chopped onions,
chopped ginger.
Garlic.
Put a little water in there.
Kiwi.
That little bit of kiwi
makes a difference?
Yes.
He put in his much garlic
and this much ginger,
this much kiwi.
And then
we're gonna blend it.
This will break it
all the way down.
Really?
Yeah.
And then we're gonna put
all this stuff in there.
Sugar, soy sauce,
Korean bean paste.
I got to try this.
That's awesome!
A little sweet,
spicy miso.
Like Korean
peanut butter.
Korean red pepper flakes.
Is that hot?
It's very hot.
Okay.
And then we mix it again.
This is what the pork
gets marinated in?
Exactly.
That is awesome.
Now what do we do?
We're gonna take
the pork butt.
The regular old pork butt.
Slice it thin.
Now we take our sliced pork.
Got it.
We get that marinated.
It's gonna soak up
the marinade.
Uh-huh.
Which, the marinade
is the bomb.
And how long
will it marinate?
For at least a day.
Fire it up.
So we got the spicy pork.
Let's hear a little bit.
A little caramelization
on the outside. Yeah.
Put a little sesame oil
on there.
Got it.
Kimchi, chopped it up
and mix it all in there.
All the flavors coming out.
So good.
Jasmine rice. This is sauce
we made to flavor the rice.
A lot of work for a burrito,
bro.
Exactly.
And then scallions.
Give it some nice color.
Take the tortilla shell,
get that nice and heated up.
The whole mixture
right there.
Look at this.
Mung beans.
Love 'em.
Julienned cucumbers.
A little bit of hot sauce.
Sour cream.
This I don't get.
And then
a little bit of nori.
This is the oddest burrito
I've ever seen.
We roll that up right there.
Parchment paper.
I'll eat right through
the parchment paper.
And then we wrap it in foil
to keep it nice and hot.
Look at that!
Mmm!
That's out of bounds!
The kimchi's a little bit sour,
a bit spicy.
The meat's got tons of flavor,
a little chew.
And the mung bean -- mmm!
Dude, that is seriously
the bomb.
Nice job.
Rocked it out.
Thanks, bro.
BANKS:
Spicy pork kimchee burrito.
The kimchi
really comes through.
It's spicy,
and there's a little tang.
Here you go.
A little zing, a little zang.
It is delicious.
It's really good.
Spicy pork tacos!
Every single plate
is delicious.
Sloppy Jojo.
And you get a huge portion.
FIERI: From Chinese
yellow curry chicken...
It's nice and creamy.
FIERI:
...to Korean beef short ribs.
Up in 30 seconds, okay?
And check out
the pork chop value meal.
Sweet chili fried pork chops
right here.
Two pork chops
with a mound of French fries.
This is just
something else.
They've got the perfect sauce
for it.
It's really tasty.
We're gonna make
the marinade
for the sweet chili fried
pork chops.
Got it.
The ginger, onions, garlic.
And then --
Of course...
A little bit of kiwi.
A little bit of water.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, it smells awesome.
Add some soy sauce, sugar.
Whisk.
We'll take the pork chops,
marinade all over it.
This is the super marinade.
I can just smell it.
This is my kind of food.
And how long will this marinate?
Another day.
Now what are we making?
We're gonna make the finishing
sauce for the marinade.
Put a little honey in there.
White vinegar.
Sesame oil in there.
Sesame seeds.
We're deep-frying
the pork chops.
After we deep fry it,
this is the sauce that's
gonna get put on there?
Exactly.
The pork chop's marinated.
We'll dust it with
just simple corn starch
and all-purpose flour.
So you get that extra
little crunch.
This goes in the fryer.
As it is?
Nice and golden brown.
Take that sauce,
pour it all over it.
We're still cooking this?
And then we're gonna put it
on the flat grill oven.
And a little bit
more sauce.
Candies up on it, got ya.
Get the French fries
on there.
French fries?!
Of course.
Pork chops go
right on top of that.
Oh, my gosh!
Mmm!
Out of bounds.
The crunchiness of the fries
soaking up the sauce.
When you cook it down there
in the fryer,
it kind of renders some
of the fat out of it,
so you're left
with the meat.
Where does this come from?
More the Korean side.
Really?
But then it has a little bit
of American style, too,
because you got
the fried pork chops.
Nailed it!
Sweet chili pork chop.
It's the perfect mixture
of sweet and spicy.
They fry it just right.
And then fries
on the side.
It gives it
that American twist.
Two minutes on the Sloppy Jojo,
okay?
I don't find this kind of food
anywhere else.
Kimchee burrito out!
MAN: It's one of those little
great places,
and the food is delicious.
Looks really good!
BANKS: Oh, you like that?
It is a cool spot.
I will be back.
Please, don't close early.
FIERI: Coming up, things
are getting wild in Phoenix...
Let's get this party
started.
...at a Thai spot
skewering up pork...
Nothing can go wrong
in this situation.
...and dishing out
dragon eggs?
Dynamite.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Scottsdale, Arizona,
at one of the greatest places
you could stay -- Sanctuary.
Oh, I'm not here for "Triple D."
No, I'm here to pick up
their executive chef --
my buddy,
Chef Beau MacMillan.
You ready to go?
Let's do it, bro!
Come on!
All right!
♪♪
So this is the joint?
Bro, don't worry,
this place is legit!
It better be.
This is the Wild Thaiger.
♪♪
Pad see-ew chicken.
The best Thai food
I've ever had.
MAN:
This is the Thai destination
in Phoenix.
You should not
miss this place.
Here's your ginger fish.
The best restaurant
in Phoenix.
Snap.
Thank you.
My mother didn't cook
like this.
FIERI:
But Olashawn Weaver's did.
My mom is a chef,
and so I learned from her.
And after life
in the corporate world,
she went back to her roots
and opened this joint in '03.
Wild Thaiger is really good,
authentic kind of Bangkok-style
Thai food.
How did it get the name
the Wild Thaiger?
The Wild Thaiger.
I wanted it to be a little bit
more like a culinary adventure.
Chefs gone wild.
Boom, boom -- pshw!
It's always fresh,
it's bright, it's vibrant.
Dragon eggs in the window.
The dragon eggs are great.
Pork, shrimp, and crab meatball
wrapped in a wonton wrapper.
Then their either
fried or steamed.
What are we gonna make?
Dragon eggs.
Let's start it.
So we have trimmed pork loin.
Gonna get it
nice and smooth.
Looks like
meat cotton candy.
You get a little spoon in there,
does that curl up
for Uncle Beau?
We're not quite pureed,
but we're not far from it.
Now we do the bay shrimp.
Yes. Okay.
♪♪
The ground pork.
Then we're going to add...
crab.
Ooh, a little crab action.
Yeah.
Sugar.
Okay.
Lots of it.
Oyster sauce.
Very nice.
This is
Golden Mountain seasoning.
It had, like, a little smokiness
to it, had a little --
Caramel.
A little caramel to it,
a little fortified soy
kind of.
Almost a little fish sauce
in it, too.
Yeah, but not as dark
as, like, the soy sauce.
Then we're gonna put in
some garlic.
Pepper.
Some eggs.
We're gonna add in
a little oil.
♪♪
Okay, now we're gonna
stuff the wontons.
Get a nice heaping spoonful.
And we're gonna
put them in there,
and you're gonna
wrap them up.
Now, are we gonna steam these
or fry these?
Both kinds.
We can do steamed --
Well,
which one do you like?
I like --
Talk to me.
I do half and half.
Wow!
Gonna steam them first.
How long do they steam?
15 minutes.
As soon as they come out
of the steamer,
we're gonna drop them
in the fryer.
Do they come with a special
sauce or anything?
Yes, and we're gonna
make the sauce.
Soy sauce, vinegar.
Just regular white vinegar?
Mm-hmm.
Worcestershire.
Okay.
Sugar.
Put some fire on there.
As soon as our dragon sauce is
ready, we'll enjoy our dragon...
Eggs.
♪♪
There's steamed ones.
Grab the fried ones.
That looks like
a big fried chicken wing.
I'm getting excited right there.
Look at that thing.
Pour the dragon egg sauce
on top.
Big rings of jalapeño.
A little cilantro on top.
And toasted garlic.
Nice.
You going deep-fried,
brother?
Yeah.
Got ya.
I'm going steamed.
You're going steamed.
Mmm!
You eat the whole thing?
Mm-hmm.
That sauce,
nice vinegar balance.
Wicked good.
Those are killer.
Don't worry about this
being my show or anything.
[ Laughs ]
Dynamite.
Yee-haw!
Not too spicy,
not too salty.
Told you
this place was legit.
MAN: These are really good.
It excites the palate,
it really does.
They're very flavorful,
especially in the sauce.
So, these are
three of my buddies.
This is Joey D., this is Craig,
and this is Danny.
And we're all down here
'cause everybody's into
this off-road motor sport,
it's called side-by-sides.
You ever had Thai food
like this?
This is different. It's like
a totally different combination.
It's awesome, it's great.
I have not had anything
like this
in any other place in Phoenix.
Such beautiful, creative food.
MAN: Just these gorgeous plates
of food.
You almost don't want to
eat them they're so beautiful.
Mu yang, sticky rice,
and papaya salad.
What's not to like
about meat on a stick?
What's next?
Next up, mu yang.
Okay, pork on a skewer.
And this gets served
on top of a papaya salad.
Green papaya salad.
With Thai chilies.
I think
that's my middle name.
This is a marinade.
We're gonna start off
with coconut milk.
Do you use a lot
of coconut milk?
All the time.
I love it.
This is --
That's Golden Mountain sauce
again.
Veggie oil, garlic.
Black pepper.
Granulated sugar.
And oyster sauce.
[ Whistles ]
Whisk it.
Whisk it real good!
Cilantro.
And then
we're gonna add pork.
Nothing can go wrong
in this situation.
And more pork.
Massage it.
We're gonna let it marinate
24 hours, and we're good to go.
Yes.
Now we're gonna
grill the pork.
To build some crunchification
and get some nice crust to it.
Papaya salad.
Pork skewers.
♪♪
There you go.
Looks bomb, bro.
Mmm!
The coconut,
props for that.
So sweet.
Really, really good.
A little caramelization
of the sugar.
Sugar.
Mmm!
Ridiculous.
All right, papaya salad.
Mmm!
Mm-hmm.
Fresh garlic.
Great little heat in there.
Nice and fresh, really bright.
♪♪
Mmm!
You nailed it.
Meat is tender.
It's got a lot of, like, really
intense flavor within the meat.
I really like her papaya salad.
And it's fresh.
The best Thai food
you ever had.
That's exactly
what I tell them.
I would tell 'em, like,
"Yo, I got this spot!"
You got to
come check it out.
Joey D. and me and the guys
gonna hang out.
Thai food. Word!
Just a great experience.
One of my favorite restaurants
of all time.
Out of bounds.
Stay true to your roots, kid,
'cause you're knocking it
out of the park.
Yeah, we will be back.
Without question.
Tonight.
More skewers, more eggs.
More eggs.
Let's get
this party started.
Was that a road trip or what?!
But don't worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this great country!
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
Whoa!
Nailed it!
[ Laughter ]
♪♪