I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Then wondered when
this was gonna start.
It's an all-inclusive,
all-you-can-eat
Flavortown buffet.
I'll be in booth eight
in the back, asleep.
From Maui to Los Angeles...
Wow!
...we've got fried chicken...
Gonna be a line down
the street on that one, baby.
...beer-can chicken...
Come on down!
You're gonna get all of it,
and half of it, too.
...real-deal ramen...
I'm really impressed,
man.
...and killer 'cue.
When we talk pork belly,
everybody gets down with it.
Plus, proper fish and chips...
-I'd eat that all day long.
-Yeah.
...fired up in a funkalicious
food truck.
That wasn't my prettiest bite,
but, dang, it's good.
[ Chuckles ]
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
I'm here in Maui
at the Kihei Kalama Village,
also known as the home
of Fat Daddy's BBQ,
and last time I was here, man,
I was enjoying
some great barbecue,
and I didn't even realize
that over the way,
well, there's a place
where three surfer dudes
are serving up Hawaiian,
Southwestern,
and Pacific Rim cuisine.
I hear it's the bomb.
This is Three's Bar & Grill.
♪♪
-How's that chicken?
-Working hard, working hard.
-[ Imitates chicken clucking ]
-[ Laughs ]
This is my favorite
restaurant on Maui.
Firing fish taco.
Everything they do here
is very well done.
MORRIN: Pulled pork quesadilla
going on the plate.
I love supporting the boys.
FIERI: Who've been supporting
each other since Travis Morrin,
Jaron Blosser,
and Cody Christopher
bonded in the biz.
Nine years ago now, we were
at a restaurant in Wailea.
One day he just, like,
you know --
"You guys want to start
a catering company?"
FIERI:
Which grew into this big spot,
mashing up a taste trifecta
going from southwest spice
to Pacific favorites.
WOMAN:
Three's Traditional Ramen.
MAN: I ate the ramen for about
a year straight.
The noodles, the pork belly.
Absolutely delicious.
So, we're getting ready to make
the ramen broth right now.
MORRIN: Mm-hmm.
Roasted chicken backs.
And these are
local pork bones.
So, we got Maui onion,
carrots, daikon, celery,
and parsley stems.
Kombu -- dried kelp.
Very necessary.
Some sliced ginger,
whole garlic cloves,
black peppercorns,
dried shiitake mushrooms.
When they rehydrate
in the water,
they release a lot
of nice mushroom flavor.
Onto the stove.
12 hours.
All right, pork belly --
season it up, homes.
We start with scallion,
some sliced ginger,
our house teriyaki sauce.
You make it yourself?
We make it ourselves.
Fantastic.
To this we're gonna add
some sesame oil, sambal.
We're going down
on the pork belly.
And this is sake
and mirin...
Okay.
...and then whole garlic.
Got it.
Now we're gonna wrap this?
And we're gonna roast it
for six hours.
Got it.
We're just gonna go ahead
and drop the noodles
from a family that's been
making ramen noodles
for generations now.
To the sauté pan,
a little bit of bacon fat.
Thought that was hair gel.
You can use it for hair gel.
Yeah.
Well, we both --
It's how you get the ladies.
Pork belly.
Gorgeous.
Okay, so to the broth, we add
a little bit of sake and mirin
to kind of balance out
the saltiness,
and then we're gonna start
building our bowl --
chicken-infused soy sauce.
So, roasted chicken backbones --
they simmer in the soy sauce.
A little bit of bacon fat
to this.
So, our broth is hot.
Broth it like it's...
CROWD: Hot.
Thank you.
Now our noodles, kale,
shiitake mushrooms,
picked with sushi-su
and kimchi.
Raw local corn,
some green onions,
and a six-minute egg.
Oh, there you go.
Pork belly.
Chili thread.
And then last but not least,
your nori.
And there you have it.
Amazing-looking ramen.
Hey, thank you.
♪♪
That's legit.
I mean,
that's really legit.
The noodles are spot on.
The broth is the real heartbeat
of this thing,
and there's real depth
to it.
The pork belly fat.
And that's the luxurious gift...
Yeah.
...that really
pushes this over the top.
The mushrooms
are the surprise factor.
The chicken soy sauce
is the gangster, dude.
That is, like, the sleeper
in the whole deal.
You guys should be very proud.
Thank you.
I'm really impressed, man.
Ramen bowl up!
-It's so good.
-The broth, the noodles,
I like the mushrooms.
A good buddy of mine,
Dave, and Katie.
Being a local,
what do you think of the food?
Wonderful.
Been here lots of times.
It's always
a fun place to be.
MAN: The ocean's right
across the street --
get out of the water,
fill yourself
with some delicious food.
We do breakfast, lunch,
happy hour, dinner.
And catering
and you have a bar
and a food truck.
And a food truck.
They work extraordinarily
well together,
and it shows in the food.
So, what else are we gonna do,
'cause I'm gonna eat this.
I'll be in booth eight
in the back, asleep.
We're doing Asian
beer can chicken with some
bacon wok-fried
Brussels sprouts.
Real underachiever,
aren't you, son?
We're gonna make
the dry rub first.
We got chili powder,
brown sugar, black pepper,
red chili flake, coriander,
yellow curry, nutmeg.
Cinnamon?
Cinnamon.
Chinese five-spice.
Garlic powder.
Cumin?
Cumin, dried oregano...
Okay.
...celery salt, Kosher salt.
Okay, and then
we just mixy-mixy.
So, you're liberally
dry rubbing this.
We're gonna mix a little bit
with the butter,
and then we're gonna
put some under the skin.
Okay.
And then a beer.
I've been waiting.
I was wondering
when this was gonna start.
-You can have it.
-Oh.
We got more.
It's for the chicken,
probably.
And so then, we pour
a little bit in the pan,
and then uno, dos, tres.
And are we serving this whole,
are we serving a half?
We serve
a whole half chicken.
You serve
a whole-half chicken?
Whole-half chicken.
Come on down!
You're gonna get all of it,
and half of it, too.
And these are going
in the oven...?
300 degrees,
hour and 20 minutes.
Halfway through,
you get an orange hoisin glaze.
What's up next?
Our bacon wok-fried
glazed Brussels sprouts.
Okay.
We're gonna start
with bacon fat again...
Right.
...ginger,
a little bit of garlic,
bacon, carrots...
Flash-fried
Brussels sprouts.
Reduced balsamic.
And this is a mixture of
unagi sauce and kimchi base.
♪ Kimchi base,
unagi sauce ♪
It's the remix.
You haven't heard this yet.
And then just throw in
just a little bit
of fresh Thai basil.
All right, homes.
Winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
half-whole chicken dinner.
Exactly.
Take one of these guys off,
cut 'em in half.
And here is the chicken.
Throw one of these
marinated oranges in there.
There you go.
...and then just some of these
pan drippings.
And just a little bit
of a garnish.
Boom.
There you have it.
♪♪
Brother, I'm gonna
tell you something.
This isn't your everyday
Sunday chicken.
You put a beer can in it,
it elevates it.
You get the moisture,
and you get that flavor profile.
The dry rub's fantastic.
You got this nice, sweet,
orange hoisin glaze going on.
That's the kicker
right there.
♪♪
The glaze on the fried
Brussels sprouts with the bacon
and the bacon fat?
Oh.
Awesome job.
MORRIN: You got two minutes
on that beer can chicken.
This is the flavor medley.
It's very delicious.
And the chef made it
with love and aloha.
So, thanks to you,
last time I was here,
I had a fantastic experience
at Fat Daddy's BBQ
right over
in that building.
MAN: Yeah.
And you recommended this.
You know, this is my go-to
on my way home.
Everything they do,
it's on point.
MORRIN: 10 seconds on
the fresh Hawaiian fish.
It's all the little steps
and extras
that you guys give...
Yeah.
...that really
put this stuff together.
I see why you're doing so well.
Great job, brother.
Thanks, brother.
♪♪
FIERI: Next up, we're headed
to Los Angeles...
That is really,
really good.
...to track down
an Irish bloke...
[ Irish accent ]
You know William Wallace?
He loves my fish and chips.
He does.
He loves 'em.
...dishing the fish
the U.K. way.
[ Normal voice ]
You must be doing it right,
and I think you are.
I'm sweating
from that ramen.
See that?
That's ramen sweat.
Ramen sweat.
I don't need
to go to the gym now.
I can just eat ramen.
♪♪
I'm here
in Los Angeles, California,
and there are two things
you can always expect here --
that is great weather
and a little bit of traffic.
Now, the great thing
about the weather is
it means you got
a lot of food trucks,
and if you need a reason
to sit in a lot of traffic,
it's to come to a food truck
like this
where the menu's really simple
and authentic.
And the owner --
he's got an accent to prove it.
This is BatterFish.
Is the line always like this?
♪♪
Picking up catfish
and a cod curry.
MAN: I'd had fish and chips
for years,
and I've never found
anything like this.
It's crispy.
It's always fresh.
I'm looking for that
truck every time.
FIERI:
It's a game of cat and mouse
the locals have been playing
since Dublin native
Jason Killalee
traded his high-rent restaurant
for this culinary cruiser.
What'd you come
to the States for?
I actually came to study
theater in New York.
And then to L.A.
to make it big.
But it was years
of waiting tables
and the lack of real-deal
fish and chips
that pushed him
to open his own joint.
What makes
great fish and chips?
A nice piece of fresh fish,
good, firm potatoes,
obviously the best batter
you can imagine.
But doing
proper fish and chips --
I'm a fan,
hence why I'm here.
One Traditional.
WOMAN: Today, I'm having
the traditional cod and chips.
It's nice,
good comfort food for me.
The tartar sauce is really good.
What are we making first?
Tartar sauce.
[ Irish accent ]
Tartar!
You know William Wallace?
He loves my fish and chips.
He does.
He loves 'em.
[ Laughs ]
[ Normal voice ]
All right.
You got a zesty,
dill pickle relish,
capers, and caper juice.
I'm gonna put a little
distilled vinegar.
I like
the zinginess of it.
"Zinginess"
is a culinary term.
♪♪
And that's all she wrote.
Mix with the mayo.
Splash of vinegar
just to thin out the mayo.
I like my tartar sauce to be
a little more like a sauce.
I dig it.
We're gonna trim up
our longline-caught Alaskan cod.
Take about
six to eight ounces.
And you're gonna
cut it in half...
Yep.
... so we're gonna get
a good ratio
of fish and batter.
Batter.
Got it.
It gives it a quick cook time,
which on a food truck
is important.
We have all-purpose
flour with salt.
This is distilled vinegar.
-That's interesting.
-Yep.
And some...
-Baking soda?
...baking soda.
You got to do this first
because it'll get clumpy.
You want some salt?
Yeah.
Sea salt.
There you go.
And usually
we let this rest
for about 15 minutes.
Now you can see all the bubbles
and funk going on in there.
Yeah.
So, we take our cod,
put it in the dredge.
-All-purpose flour?
-Yep.
A little bit of salt
in there, batter it,
and bring it to the fryer.
Let the fish swim
for about five minutes.
In the oil?
In the oil.
Are you double-frying
the fries?
Yes.
A little bit of salt.
Fish.
[ Whistles ]
There we go.
Our tartar sauce
and our malt vinegar.
Malt vinegar.
No lemon?
If you went to a fish-and-chips
shop in Ireland or England,
they'd throw you out
if you asked them for lemon.
Throw you out?
They'd throw you out
the window.
They'd throw you out,
they would.
I like the malt vinegar.
A little dip.
Wow.
So good.
But I appreciate that amount
of fish to that amount of crust.
That's a good ratio.
I mean, this is not greasy,
not heavy.
The little bicarbonate kick
gives it great crunch.
And fresh fish --
it's not frozen --
and proper chips,
by the way.
That is really,
really good.
-Thank you, Chef.
-Nicely done, my friend.
Traditional cod and chips.
-Thank you.
-Enjoy, mate.
It's golden,
and it's fried just right.
Can't dump enough
malt vinegar on it.
When you have fish and chips,
you got to put it on there.
When I come down to Los Angeles,
I run into all my brothers
and sisters
of one show
or another.
Well, this happens to be
1/10th of the crew
of "Guy's Grocery Games."
What do you think?
Devoured it.
Very delicious.
Really good.
FIERI: And when it comes
to playing to an L.A. crowd,
this Irish cat
is no one-trick pony.
There's always so many
different varieties of things.
I'm working on
the lobster roll right now.
It's got a little ginger to it.
I like the jumbo shrimp
or the chili catfish.
Catfish chili batter.
Enjoy.
WOMAN:
That one has nice seasoning --
not too spicy
with some mushy green peas.
It's a really nice
little treat on its side.
Before we do the catfish,
walk me through this mushy peas.
It's more popular in England
than it is in Ireland
and Scotland.
All right.
Let's see it.
-So we use sweet peas.
-Okay.
They usually make them
with steeped peas,
which are like
marrow fat peas,
but they taste terrible,
so I use the sweet peas.
-But your mom would approve?
-She loves them.
Fresh basil --
not so traditional.
A little lemon zest,
copious amounts of salt,
enough water to cover.
You put them on
just to soften them up,
and then you blitz it
in the blender.
And we're gonna serve those
with the catfish?
Yep.
We're gonna take a piece
of catfish,
do a quick marinade
with some sriracha
and some sambal.
Mix it up, get all the moisture
off the fish,
in the dredge.
Out of the dredge.
Batter it,
and drop it in the fryer.
Okay.
Four minutes.
And catfish chili,
a little Louisiana Hot Sauce,
and our tartar sauce.
And a side
of the mushy peas, please.
♪♪
Good. Tender, moist.
I think the real key
to this whole thing,
dude, is the batter.
It's nice and light,
tons of flavor.
That sambal with the little bit
of the sriracha...
that is dabbling on Asian.
Here's the bite I want --
the fish into the hot sauce,
into the tartar sauce,
stacked
with a French fry...
That wasn't my prettiest bite,
but, dang, it's good.
[ Chuckles ]
And then you come over here.
Oh, yeah, man.
Well, the basil
with the...
Lemon zest?
...lemon zest.
I'd eat that all day long.
Yeah.
Picking up --
Chili Catfish.
This is
unbelievably delicious.
I've never had catfish
I liked before.
That seasoning
on there is heaven.
He manages to keep
the chili flavor in it
and still keep it crispy.
It's very yummy.
This is our good buddy,
Fraggle.
Was on the "Triple D"
crew for years.
Break it down for me.
The sriracha's actually,
like -- it makes it pop.
There's a little bit
of something extra.
A little bit of tease.
Boom.
Creamy, spicy.
It's fantastic.
I'm a big fan of the truck.
Where he's at, we're going.
If you could make a living off
a fish and chips truck
in a town like Los Angeles,
you must be doing it right,
and I think you are.
Thank you, Chef.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up --
We're staying in L.A.
to hit up
the Grand Central Market.
Unfortunately,
there's just one fork.
That's mine.
Looking for some
Texas barbecue...
Rock star, man.
...where the bark
is worth every bite.
It's like a dog pound.
That's a lot of bark, huh?
♪♪
I'm here
in Los Angeles, California,
at the Grand Central Market.
I tell you what,
they got every type of food
you could imagine here.
And I got a lot of buddies here
in the restaurant business,
and they say that if you can
have a barbecue joint
that's going four-years strong,
well, you've got
to check it out.
This is Horse Thief BBQ.
♪♪
Beef rib, ready!
Nothing has the flavor
like this place.
MAN: Brisket plate!
I do live downtown,
work next door,
and eat here
every chance we get.
Spare rib plate ready!
It's authentic,
Texas-style barbecue.
FIERI:
Central Texas, to be exact,
'cause that's where
chef Anthony Chin
got his first taste
of the good stuff.
-How'd you get into barbecue?
-It was always a hobby.
It got real because I was
in the music business,
and I'd go
to South by Southwest.
Oh, that's exactly
what it is.
The music business
leads to barbecue.
-Yeah.
-You go down there,
you get addicted
in Austin...?
And then decided to go
to culinary school
at night while I was working,
and then the barbecue hobby
turned into
real serious business.
And the food here is no joke
whether it's classic 'cue
or a down-home favorite.
Fried chicken sandwich.
MAN: The fried chicken sandwich
is amazing.
It's juicy, but then you get
that nice crunch from the fry,
and then the slaw that's
on top of it is just awesome.
What's on the rundown here?
We're gonna
start off marinating
our boneless skin-on
chicken thighs.
Okay.
Buttermilk, hot sauce,
and then this is
our prepared dredge
that we're gonna dredge
the chicken in after.
-Just to tighten it up?
-Yep.
All right,
how long's this gonna marinate?
Overnight.
So, while that marinates,
we'll make the slaw.
-All right.
-Dig it.
-Rice wine vinegar.
Honey.
That was honey?
That was honey.
How runny is your honey...
that your
honey goes like that?
We warmed it up
so it's faster.
You're a honey heater.
Honey heater.
Not a hater, heater.
Yellow mustard.
Give this a mix.
Shredded cabbage, red onion,
parsley, salt, pepper.
-You grind that yourself?
-Yep.
You gonna do real barbecue,
you got to grind
your own black pepper.
Key.
Okay, now we're gonna
dredge the chicken.
Don't shake it too much
so it'll pick up.
And 350...
About 14 minutes.
Now we're ready
to toast our buns.
Mayo each side of the bun,
honey mustard slaw here,
picked jalapeño,
fried chicken thigh,
a little more
picked jalapeño.
And that's all she wrote.
That's it.
♪♪
That's a dynamite
fried chicken sandwich.
Thank you.
The chicken cooked perfectly --
not overly seasoned,
not under seasoned,
simple bun
that stays together.
But the key is
the rice wine vinegar and honey
and the jalapeño.
So you get this sweet,
hot vinegar going on
with the chicken,
all tying it together.
That's a bomb
chicken sandwich.
Gonna be a line down
the street on that one, baby.
Thank you.
WOMAN: The attention to detail
on the fried chicken sandwich
is what sets it apart.
Little kick
of the jalapeño.
It's perfectly dressed.
The juice factor, man.
It's just so moist.
It's one of my
favorite things here.
I just know that if I'm going
to have barbecue,
it's gonna be Horse Thief.
How you doing?
FIERI:
Which is just one of the spots
tucked right outside
this downtown L.A.
food market Mecca.
This joint, I don't know
how I missed it.
Maybe 'cause I'm always
inside the market
and not on the outside,
but this is worth it
to come outside.
A great place to come up
and get some good food
and some good drinks.
The courtyard out here
looks like
it's your own
private restaurant.
We share it with the market,
but we designed it.
You deigned it,
it's connected directly to you.
You have a gate
that shuts everybody out,
so it basically is yours.
Pretty much.
I kind of like
small owner type places,
and this fills the bill
on every aspect.
So, here's the deal --
We're at Grand Central Market
in Los Angeles.
We're at a funky joint
called the Horse Thief.
We come back...
Smoked pork belly.
The smoked pork belly here
is up there
with some of the best I've had.
FIERI:
And it's coming your way
right after the break.
And I'll have the fried
chicken sandwich on the way.
All right.
♪♪
Welcome back.
I'm hanging out
at the Horse Thief
here at the Grand Central Market
in Los Angeles
and just happened
to be touring the Market
during the commercial,
and I find
one of my favorite chefs,
dominates on
"Guy's Grocery Games,"
my buddy
Chef Philip Frankland Lee.
So, I know you wouldn't mind
that I bring this big-shot L.A.
restaurant chef to come in
'cause when we talk pork belly,
everybody gets down with it.
CHIN: Smoked pork belly
with apple-fennel slaw.
I love the smoked pork belly.
It's cooked so perfectly.
It's super delicious.
-Let's get in the pork belly.
-First, we're gonna brine it.
You got water, brown sugar,
Kosher salt.
Drop this in.
-And how long?
-Overnight.
A simple brine.
This is about honoring
the ingredient,
really bringing out the flavors
of the pork belly, yeah?
Yep, and not
overpowering the wood.
What, do you guys have
pork belly club or something?
Am I not in?
I'm not welcome to be
in the pork belly club?
The pork belly's down
in the marinade.
We'll do the dry rub
when it comes out.
In the meantime,
apple-fennel slaw.
We're gonna start off with apple
cider vinegar, fennel honey.
I toast fennel, pour honey
over it to let it steep.
Napa cabbage, green apple,
basil, mint...
Love a little mint in my slaw.
...fennel, salt,
fresh cracked pepper.
You know
that's my expectation.
I think we should have
a couple tasting utensils,
and unfortunately,
there's just one fork.
That's mine.
I eat with my hands.
Fantastic.
We'll just dive in.
-I love the black pepper.
-I love the basil.
I'll take a side of that
for sure.
All right.
Dry rub --
Brown sugar,
sweet paprika, onion,
chili powder, dried mustard.
So, maybe following
under the lines
of a traditional
barbecue rub?
Correct.
Granulated garlic,
cracked pepper, and Kosher salt.
Got it.
Pork belly time.
In here.
Even coat.
-In the smoker, 2 and a quarter?
-Yep.
What kind of wood are you using?
It's post oak.
Post oak. Right.
10 hours. What do you want
to do for 10 hours?
-Let's go surf!
-Cool.
That's what we're doing next.
So, we're gonna plate
our apple-fennel slaw.
Now we're gonna pull
the meat.
Listen, if it can
get out of there by itself,
I want to see it.
Look at that.
The bark on that.
It's like a dog pound.
That's a lot of bark, huh?
It's gonna go right on top
of our slaw, spicy mayo.
All right.
Great smoke, not too much smoke.
Super tender and juicy,
and when I saw you do
the spicy mayo,
I was like,
"That's weird."
But it's delicious.
Gives a silkiness to it.
♪♪
That's my favorite salad.
That is really, really good.
And this right here just has
the nice kiss of smoke.
And the sugar content
is perfect.
It has just that amount
of sweetness,
especially
for the spicy mayo.
Like, it just counteracts,
like, perfectly.
Cool. Thank you, Chef.
It is really good.
Wow, listen
to somebody get all...
I like to eat!
...cheffy-hosty on me over here.
I don't know if he just
discovered the Horse Thief
or the fact
that Philip Frankland Lee
can host the show.
Wow!
Smoked pork belly.
WOMAN: The smoked pork belly
is so tender,
and the rub has
so much smoky flavor.
My buddy Abel works
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
He's in the culinary team.
What do you think, homes?
Just the right amount
of crisp on the outside,
and the slaw
compliments it really well.
In your opinion --
he's seen it all --
how would that do in competition
at "Guy's Grocery Games"?
It would be
a big thumbs up.
Smoked beef rib!
WOMAN:
I love Horse Thief.
I can't come to downtown
without hitting this place.
The barbecue is wonderful,
and the people are wonderful.
Rock star, man.
Well done.
Thank you.
♪♪
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
It's funny when you talk
about runny honey
and honey-heater haters.
People that don't
like runny honey,
they're called
"honey-heater haters."
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughing ] Where --
Where are we at? Where?