Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hey, wait, wait, wait!
...we're getting fried...
Come on.
...and pied...
So you just made a gigantic,
Cajun dumpling.
...with some shenanigans
on the side.
-Barbecue, barbecue, barbecue!
We've got rocking ramen
in Florida...
Gorgeous!
a righteous taste
of New Orleans...
Oh! Start it up.
And in Lansing, Michigan...
Do you mind if I chuck the bowl?
...all kinds of
crazy wings and things.
Whoo-hoo!
I got the lottery!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, you find yourself
in New Orleans,
and you don't have
the '68 to drive,
you're in the French Quarter,
and you say,
"Listen, I want to get out
of this tourist area,
and I want to go eat some of
the food the locals love."
Here's what you do --
you get the uptown streetcar,
you cruise it along
from Canal Street
to S. Carrollton and Jeannette,
walk across the street,
it's a joint you got to check.
This is Bourrée.
♪♪
It's just, like,
a little Cajun smokehouse.
Hear it crackle.
Oh, my goodness.
-It's off the beaten path.
It's become kind of a place
for foodies to go.
-So gotdang succulent!
-Where'd you learn to cook?
I went to Le Cordon Bleu
in London and in Sydney.
[ English accent ]
Oh, didn't you now?
FIERI: [ Normal voice ]
And Chef Nathanial Zimet
put the education to good use.
After Hurricane Katrina,
he and his business
partner, James Denio,
got busy rebuilding
the NOLA food scene,
going from firing up
a food truck
to a fine-dining,
brick-and-mortar,
then this place next door.
Starting out with just
wings and daiquiries,
but now going whole hog
with the smoke and charcuterie.
The food here --
it's fun food.
Did you just get one of those
hot-sausage meat pies?
The meat pies here
are really good.
You bite into that nice,
crispy outside,
and then you get
the gooey, meaty inside.
ZIMET: Now, it's time to season
and then grind our meat
for our hot sausage
and cheese meat pie.
-So, we got that pork cubed up.
-So, we'll season it first.
-Okay.
-A little salt,
some black pepper, cayenne,
garlic powder, guajillo pepper.
Nice!
Paprika, white pepper,
onion power.
I always try to season before
I grind. I think it really...
Incorporates it
a million times more.
Intensely.
I noticed that you have this
all frozen...
-Yes.
-...so we won't gum up.
So, we do our first
coarse grind.
And then we'll go
to a fine grind?
Indeed.
So, now, we're going to
drop it into the Rondo.
-Yes.
-Beautiful. Lick the bowl.
Next thing we're gonna do
is we're gonna add these
beautiful sweet onions.
-Okay.
-Jalapeños.
-Red bell?
-Red bell pepper.
And then we season it up --
a little onion powder, cayenne.
This is
a dried jalapeño powder.
-Okay.
-And then paprika.
-I never had no paprika.
-We're fancy over here.
Next, we add
American cheese.
American cheese
has its place.
It's something that I never
had growing up, but whenever...
Oh, you want to talk
about never having it?
You didn't get to
have it either?
-No.
-Your mom's watching us
right now,
just losing it.
-Certainly.
-All right, so, cook it down.
A little bit of
mustard in there?
-Cook it down. Add the mustard.
-Shove that in my shoe.
The -- Ooh, there's
a little heat in there.
-That's that hot sausage.
-The silkiness, the unctuous,
the velvet
of that American cheese --
that's the binder.
I mean...
-That is it.
...that's bringing it
all together.
-Holds it all together.
-Okay, let's make it.
Now we're ready to
assemble our meat pie.
Now, what are these?
Empanada wrappers?
Empanada wrappers.
Yes, sir. We take
our trusty scoop.
We have some whipped egg.
That's gonna be what holds
the wrapper to itself.
Try to make sure
you get zero air in this.
You just made a gigantic,
Cajun dumpling.
[ Laughing ]
That is correct.
And then, to make
it really fancy...
-Oh, here we go.
-You have to be careful.
Sometimes you get a little
excited with the fork,
and you poke through.
-And you poke it.
And that doesn't work.
Drop it in the oil
for how long?
This gets about four
or five minutes.
We serve it with
a roasted poblano ranch.
-You make it yourself?
-Indeed.
You're a gangster.
[ Whistles ]
See, it's not steaming because
it's already hot in this place.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm! Here's what I got
for you, Chef --
you wouldn't know
there's cheese in there,
but that's
the super binder.
I give you all the props
in the world.
The spice level
is just right.
It's just bringing you up to,
"Oh, where's another daiquiri?"
[ Laughs ]
The flakiness
of the crust -- spot on.
But the kicker --
the poblano ranch.
I mean,
that's pretty stupid.
The grind is great.
It's toothsome.
You got enough
chew to it.
You've got tons of levels
of flavor inside of it.
Outstanding.
-Thank you very much.
-Real deal, man.
-Thank you.
Dropping a meat pie
one time.
The hot sausage
meat pie is great. I love it.
MAN: It actually comes out
super hot.
It's kind of torture
waiting two, three minutes.
You just want to bite in to it,
but you have to wait.
I'm gonna talk to
a couple of my buddies.
They own this convenience-store,
gas-station chain in Texas.
It's called Buc-ee's.
What do you think?
Is that ranch dressing
with the little bit of poblano?
-Yeah, the poblano ranch.
-Incredible.
Food's fantastic here.
Exciting environment.
Exciting drinks.
FIERI: Including the specialty
they built this place on --
real-deal daiquiris.
This is not the daiquiri
that you see
when you walk down through
some of the tourist areas.
-Fresh fruit daiquiris.
-Fresh fruit goes in there?
They tend to be
less sweet.
Our Hurricane is
probably our most sold,
and it's traditionally made,
so with passion fruit,
and it's awesome.
All right. So, what are you
gonna cook next?
We're doing --
Ah! Don't tell me.
I don't want you
to give away de--
You don't give away the end
of the parade, right?
You make them wait for it!
You're gonna have to wait
for it. I'm gonna finish this.
You come back, we'll
hang out with this guy,
and I know it's
gonna be great.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" in New Orleans,
hanging out in
the Riverbend area
at a funky, little
joint named Bourrée.
Known for daiquiris and sausage
and a killer meat pie
that I just had with
Chef Nathanial,
but he says he has more.
So, we're gonna talk about...
Spicy shrimp boudin.
Just for everyone that
doesn't understand "boudin",
we're making shrimp sausage.
-Correct.
Now, one of the funny
things about boudin,
a lot of folks don't know
is it has rice in it.
So, you got some
great texture.
So, it's, like, a composed
meal inside of a casing.
Right.
The spicy shrimp boudin
is so good.
It's smokey.
It's delicious. It's flavorful.
-How do we start?
-We start with some crab stock.
This comes from
the Higgins family.
They produce the
best crab in the city.
This is a crab boil.
A little sachet of sage,
thyme, and bay leaf.
Some kosher salt, cayenne
pepper, and black pepper.
Turn it on.
And as soon as this
comes up to a boil,
we will add our popcorn rice.
-Popcorn rice?
-It's an aromatic rice.
It's a long grain that comes
from local Louisiana.
-It smells like popcorn.
-We cover it.
Takes about 20 minutes.
[ Imitates popcorn popping ]
[ Laughs ]
We caramelize some onions.
Some sweet onions again?
This takes about
an hour and a half.
-Really? To caramelize?
-Properly caramelize, yeah.
Once those are low and slow,
what's gonna happen?
These are Gulf shrimp.
Cook these pretty quickly.
Salt, pepper,
and some cayenne pepper.
The last thing you add is your
parsley and your green onion?
Yes, sir.
And that and the rice
get mixed together?
Everything gets
mixed together.
Let's give it a taste.
-Wow!
-That's got some heat.
All the liquid
to cook that rice --
you said crab stock?
-That's it.
-Mmm!
And that little sweet
from the caramelized onions --
man, that's good!
Put it into
the sausage stuffer.
And these are
rinsed hog casings.
And you're by hand,
all the time, all the sausage?
All the time.
And then, we do six inches.
We then smoke them.
We're gonna smoke
on top of this?
-Correct.
-Oh! Start it up.
We do it for about an hour
and a half to 155 degrees.
What kind of wood
are we gonna use?
-Only oak wood.
-You're gonna get smoke.
You're gonna get heat.
You're gonna get shrimp
inside of a natural casing.
I'll take all of them.
-And that's how we serve it.
Okay, tell me the story
about the fries.
We fry them in canola,
toss them with salt and pepper,
and then,
this is the magic.
80 percent beef fat,
20 percent smoked lardons.
So, beef fat
and smoked pork fat.
Dude.
Why did we sit here
and mess around
with making
all this other stuff
when all we really wanted
was the beef tallow fries?
These fries are
stupid good!
What was this again?
-That's our shrimp boudin.
Those little shrimp, they're
just perfect in that, you know?
These are tender. They're nice.
They're delicate.
The rice cooked down
just the right way.
It's still got a bit
of texture to it.
The spice mellowed out
a little bit from the smoke,
but you get a really nice,
big mouth of smoke in there.
Wow!
It has a really nice snap
when you bite into it.
It's like a party in your mouth,
but it's not too crowded.
You've had some
fries in your day.
Where do they stack up?
-At the top.
-I love this place.
-Bourrée does it best.
This is the place
everybody wants to see
when they go on vacation.
I go around,
and I roll with
a bunch
of kulinary gangsters,
and without question,
you're one, dude.
-Thank you, brother. Thank you.
-Nicely done.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up
in St. Petersburg, Florida...
There you go.
...a Japanese joint
big on flavor...
Salty, sweet,
acid, heat.
...and definitely
not short on personality.
-[ Imitates dog barking ]
-It's "Tommy Boy" all day long.
-What's your wife's name?
-Colina.
Want to sing
to her or something?
♪ Colina, I love you ♪
♪ Let me see your land
of milk and honey ♪
He might've been drinking a bit,
but in New Orleans, that's okay.
♪♪
I'm here at beautiful
St. Petersburg, Florida
to check out a joint.
Actually, I'm here
to check out a crazy buddy.
[ Laughing ]
His name's Brunch.
Now, he doesn't take
very many things serious,
except for his ramen business.
This is Brunch,
and this is Buya!
Buya, Buya ramen!
Okay I have the pork gyoza.
It's one of the best restaurants
that I've eaten in the city.
Seafood ramen
in the window.
Everything has
layers of flavors.
Japanese influenced.
Traditional, as well.
FIERI: Served up by the
"Abbott and Costello"
of the local culinary scene,
my buddy Brunch,
formerly known
as Brian Wojtowicz,
and Chef Mike Sponaugle.
Mike and Brian, they really
do push the needle.
Bring an off-beat attitude
to Asian cuisine.
We're the traditional
izakaya.
Izakaya is a Japanese
gastropub -- eat small bites,
get a cocktail,
get a drink, Japanese whiskey.
So, Japanese whiskey
is a big thing?
it's a huge thing.
It's very smooth.
They're very, very creative
whether for a cocktail,
a great bowl of ramen.
-Duck ramen in the window.
Crispy duck ramen is probably
my favorite dish here.
The broth is fantastic.
Let's get into
making the broth.
-So, this is the tonkotsu broth.
-Okay.
A pork-bone based broth.
-What goes first?
-We're doing pigs feet.
-I love pork.
-Chicken feet for the collagen.
Right, that's what gets
that silky, creaminess of it.
Did you go to collagen?
-Yeah, I went there twice.
-Chicken necks.
Green onions.
Got garlic cloves.
Kombu, which is a seaweed.
-Dried seaweed.
Adds a little salinity
to the broth itself.
-He uses big words.
-He does.
Yeah, he's a big-word man.
-A little bit of ginger.
Okay.
Then we add distilled water,
as well.
Distilled water?
Tonkotsu broth is very
specific in the texture
and the viscosity
and all of the above,
so distilled water
is critical.
And it simmers for 22 hours.
They we strain it.
And we'll be ready
to start making this.
Yep. Now we're gonna do
the duck confit.
-You know what that is?
-Yes.
What is that?
-Duck feet.
[ Laughing ]
Duck feet.
It's "Tommy Boy"
all day long.
So, we're gonna start with our
duck quarters, fresh thyme...
-Got it.
-...garlic.
We're gonna do bay
leaves, salt, pepper...
-And...
-Most importantly, the duck fat.
Now we're gonna close it up
and put it in the oven
for about eight hours
at about 200, 210 degrees.
All right, so,
now it's go time.
The duck is rested and cooled.
You shred it by hand.
Well, now we're gonna compose
the crispy duck ramen.
We're gonna start off with
a little bit of sesame oil.
This is takana. It's a
pickled-mustard green.
Shiitake mushrooms.
Bok choy.
Okay. So, that gets
a quick little sauté.
Then we go back
to the tonkotsu broth.
So, while we're bringing
this up to a simmer,
we're gonna use fresh ramen.
These needs about 30
seconds in boiling water.
Got it.
And this is gonna
go right in your broth.
Finishing
its cooking process.
Okay, a little
sesame oil down.
Crisp up the duck.
-And just pour right in?
Yep, pour right in.
All right,
now the duck goes on?
We're gonna do bean
shoots for garnish.
Chopped scallions.
Finish with the traditional,
soft-boiled egg.
-Okay.
-This is gonna be
marinated in soy sauce.
Sesame seeds.
So, this is a little
Japanese ladle that we use.
Part of Japanese culture,
as well, is all about the slurp.
-That's how you want it to go?
-Absolutely.
It means to him,
"Congratulations.
You did a great job."
[ Slurps ]
With the tonkotsu,
the broth itself is spot-on.
There's a lot of
really nice silkiness.
Very light.
Very rich.
I like the crispy
duck that's going on.
The fresh shoots
in there are great.
Really great dish.
I mean, you guys are taking
the time to do it right
to give the people
a true experience.
[ Slurps ]
Nicely done.
-Thank you.
Tasty duck.
Excellent job, guys.
-Appreciate it.
-I have two duck ramen.
Very delicious
and well balanced.
And the duck is cooked
extremely well.
-How's that broth?
-It's fantastic.
This is my family.
We eat a lot of ramen.
So, I figured
the best ones to give me
the real-deal opinion
is this three.
So, what do you think
of the ramen?
It's great. That duck
is really tender actually.
We all know Brunch.
We all know how crazy Brunch is.
As many years
as we have known
Brunch and seen the
many antics of Brunch...
He's growing up at 40!
-He's growing up! Awe!
-Awe!
[ Imitates dog barking ]
Brian's a ball of energy.
He's a fun guy to be around.
Mike's a class act.
His knowledge of the food
and how things play together
are very, very well thought out.
And shishito peppers
to share.
The shishito peppers
are delicious.
Some are hot.
Some are not.
The char gives it
the best flavor.
This is the blistering
shishito peppers.
When I see shishito peppers
on a menu, I got to have them.
SPONAUGLE:
Garlic oil goes in the pan.
Hot pan is critical.
-And the shishitos go down.
Are you a shishito fan?
-Love them.
-I see you sweating, big guy.
Aw, yeah. It's hot.
We actually put
a little char on it,
so you actually have this
recurring theme of smoke flavor,
smoke flavor, smoke flavor,
barbecue, barbecue, barbecue.
BOTH: Barbecue, barbecue,
barbecue, barbecue!
-Nice and blistered up.
-Nice and blistered.
Then we're gonna go in
with our ginger.
Hit it with a little
bit of garlic.
-There you go.
-Nice toss.
Blow torch.
We're gonna do a little bit of
the sugar and smoked sea salt.
You're gonna get
that sweet element.
You're also gonna
get that smoke,
and you're gonna get
that salt.
House-cured black garlic.
A little bit of rice
wine vinegar.
A little bit of soy.
And now we're gonna plate.
-It smells so good.
-Oh.
-We're gonna sprinkle with
brown sugar
and smoked sea salt.
A little bit of togarashi.
-Nice.
-Gorgeous!
♪♪
Delicious.
I like that little crunch
you get from the
caramelization from the sugar,
but it's that salty,
sweet, acid, heat.
Shishito is such
a great foundation.
It's a conduit that brings
all of those flavor profiles.
Yeah. Mmm!
Great job, guys.
-Thank you.
-Shishito peppers to share.
And you never know
which one's gonna be hot.
WOMAN:
When you get a hot one,
it doesn't really
blow your mouth up.
-The shishitos?
-Those are insane.
All right, what do
you think there Snox?
You proud of Brunch?
Did he do a good job?
Big, fat star.
It's just a great restaurant.
I'm really impressed.
When you got Brunch
as a front man,
he is the perfect maître d'
of the entire system.
-Absolutely.
-You guys are sticking to
the tradition doing what you
and doing it right.
Well done!
Congratulations.
FIERI: Up next...
Yeah!
...these wicked wings
in Lansing, Michigan...
You got your chicken emporium
helmet on or something.
...are just the gateway to...
♪ Bring on the gizzards ♪
♪♪
I'm here
in East Lansing, Michigan.
Man, I haven't
been here in awhile.
Back when "Triple D"
first started,
we went to place called
"Joe's Gizzard City".
And speaking of gizzards,
I'm here to check out a joint
that's frying gizzards,
chicken wings,
and anything else you want.
You see, their motto
is "You buy, we fry."
This is Eastside market.
Three pig skins, up!
It's like nothing
you've ever had before.
MAN:
I didn't know how to explain it.
It's just good food.
-Wings going down!
FIERI: Good food that was born
out of some tough times.
Well, I got out of prison
about five years ago.
You come out
and there's not
a lot of people
that want to give you a job.
There's not a lot of people that
want to give you an opportunity.
Nobody would give me a job.
But Henry Meyer's
parents stood by him,
helping him start
a fish market from scratch
that's grown into
a full-fledged restaurant.
-So, who taught you how to cook?
-I learned a lot in prison.
-Did you work in the kitchen?
-Yeah.
Six wing dinner up!
Everybody asks
for the wings.
The seasoning really
sets it right off.
They are excellent.
What are we
making first, buddy?
Making our house seasoning.
Lemon pepper blend,
a lemon peel,
black pepper,
garlic powder.
-Got it.
-And then we hand mix.
Because if you put
your foot in there...
No feet.
Okay, so, this is our dry batter
that we're gonna use.
Next up, we're gonna make
marinade for our wings.
Some of this house
seasoning, seasoned salt...
-Got it.
-...Old Bay.
-Old Bay on the wings?
-Old Bay on the wings.
Yep.
We're gonna shake it up,
and then we're gonna bring
our whole case of wings...
And you're leaving
them all connected?
That's what everybody
likes -- are whole wings.
And how long is this
gonna sit on here?
At least 24 hours,
but usually 48.
And you're going
through how many?
-About 2,500 wings a day.
-The chicken king over here.
I got get you like the chicken
emporium helmet or something.
-Next step?
-We're gonna make
our house chicken flour.
High-gluten flour.
-Okay.
Then we'll go with
our special chicken fry.
-Got it.
-Seasoned salt.
-The Old Bay again.
-Old Bay. Yep.
House seasoning here.
Granulated garlic.
And black pepper.
-So, you're not shy on flavor.
-No.
All right, so, now we
take the seasoned wings.
-Those go in here.
-Dredge them around.
-Yep.
-To the fryer?
-What kind of oil?
Soy bean oil.
Come on!
-Awe!
Now we're gonna put some of
our house seasoning on there.
That is a mess of wings.
♪♪
Mmm! That's getting...
Ah!
That 48-hour, dry-rub
marinade you're doing.
That's just soaking
all the way through.
-Yeah.
-And you put a nice,
thin dry batter on it.
There's no fat. He's really
cooked those wings down.
Yep.
Only thing this needs is
a picnic basket and a blanket.
SERVER:
I got your six wing dinner.
They're moist.
They're meaty.
It's crunchy,
and it's delicious.
MAN: This place has evolved
in the last five years.
Henry Meyer and his staff
have done a wonderful job.
FIERI:
And Henry's always working on
paying things forward.
I try to
only hire felons.
Try to give them another chance
to get a fresh start.
Everybody here
really respects the fact
that I'm giving them
the chance.
FIERI: And customers are given
the chance to dive
into some interesting,
local delicacies.
Pound of gizzards up!
The gizzards, man,
just soft, crunchy...
It's a really good flavor.
It's not heavily battered.
Do you know what
the gizzard is?
Yeah. It's about
the second part of the throat,
if I'm not mistaken.
-Mm, yeah.
-Digestive tract.
-Yeah!
-Right around here, I'd say.
You're right there!
So, we're done fixing
to fry some up!
We've been boiling these
with some pepper
and some seasoned salt
for about three hours.
Not long enough! The people
love gizzards, though.
We sell them
by the pound.
Pound of gizzards.
We're gonna
dump some water on them.
-All right.
-Add our seasoned salt.
House seasoning.
Now we're gonna mix
this up real good.
Okay.
Now these go into the fridge --
24 to 48 hours.
So, we've got
our boiled, chilled,
two-day marinated
gizzards.
Yep. And then
we're gonna put some...
-Gizzard-marinated juice.
-Yep
And we're gonna add
some of our chicken flour
to that to make
a thin, wet batter.
-Okay.
-Now we're gonna take those
and we're gonna put
them in our flour.
-You mind if I chuck the bowl?
-Nope, that's fine.
Okay.
Then we're gonna
sift this real good.
♪ Bring on the gizzards ♪
♪ Give me one, two,
or three ♪
[ Trumpet flourish ]
Ha ha ha!
You know Guy's nervous
when he's singing.
Got to put our seasoning on.
Please.
Same time?
You want to
"Thelma and Louise" it?
-Yeah.
-Okay. Whoo!
I got the lottery! I got --
Hey, wait, wait, wait! Hank!
How did you pick out
the little one?
It's got great texture.
It's got good chicken flavor.
They're not overbattered.
That's really good.
-Good.
I think I've grown
as a person.
-You have.
-Since 10 years ago.
I was a little scared when
I was at Joe's Gizzard City.
Have you ever been there?
-I have.
-Good guy.
-Very good guy.
I brought him down.
I want him to try your gizzards.
I want him to say,
"You're a gizzard wizard."
And what do we have here?
-Those are our famous pig skins.
That's crazy.
Give me the rundown.
How does it work?
-We take bacon.
Uh-huh.
-And we put it in either
water or buttermilk,
dip it in our chicken
batter, and deep fry it.
Comes out like
a bacon potato chip.
In the world
of fried bacon,
pretty much right now
you're leading the pack
because I don't think
I've ever seen it like that.
MAN: Pound of gizzards up!
There's some "Triple D" legends,
and this is one of them.
Joe Bristol from
Joe's Gizzard City.
You think this is a good
representation of gizzards?
Yes, I do.
And the great thing is, a little
bit different than yours.
-It is.
-Is he in the gizzard gang?
-Oh, absolutely.
-They're cooked perfectly.
My buddy Shaun, my buddy John --
what do you think?
-They're pretty good!
-Pound of Cajun gator up!
Good food from
anything you order.
-They're just doing it right.
-Yes, sir.
My friend,
I'm gonna tell you --
turning your life
around is one thing,
having great parents that
support you is another thing,
but taking all of that
and doing it right
and being proud
of what you're doing
and helping others
at the same time,
well, that's
a whole other level.
And I've got to
tell you something,
it makes the food taste
that much better.
-Thank you.
-Fantastic.
-Really impressive.
So, was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
-We do liver, too.
-You -- Oh! There we go.
-You don't like chicken liver?
-Mm...
I'm not a big fan of a lot
of the parts that had a job.
Ha ha ha ha!