Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins and dives.
This trip...
You guys ready for this? Watch.
We're hitting
righteous restaurants
keeping things all
in the family.
Everybody, from the
aunts to your mom,
your wife to your daughters...
From a husband-and-wife
duo in Santa Fe...
This is crazy tasty.
To multigenerational
joints still going strong.
This is how you've
always done it?
Always.
Like a pancake
paradise in Jersey...
Like pigs in the
blanket gone wild?
Yeah.
Off the chain
chili in Seattle...
There's like 85 different
spices going on in there.
Bomb burgers in Utah...
Gosh. That's really good.
Real-deal Chicago Italian...
Can I get a gallon
of that to go?
And a meat lover's
dream in Vancouver.
You are the beefinator.
So get ready for this
full hour of food and family.
That's what I'm talking
about, right there!
That's all right here,
right now on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
♪♪
Seattle is known
for its killer food,
and there's this joint
we've just got to
check out in Ballard,
an industrial area right across
the bridge from downtown.
This third-generation
father-and-son team
run a one-of-a-kind parlor
filled with local flavor.
You stirring that
chili over there?
Stir the chili?
Stir the chili, Big Phil.
Come on. Get to work.
Phil Semandiris
and his son, Mike,
take their chili
very seriously...
I love it in a chili
burger, chili dog.
I love my chili.
And so do the locals.
How was it?
Perfect.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
It's got a little kick?
Oh, yeah.
Tasty.
This defines chili.
And chili defines
everything at this joint.
You see, Mike's Chili Parlor
is true to its name...
This is your
standard Mike's bowl.
On whatever you order.
Chili fries, very good.
What are you having?
Chili dog.
Chili dog?
Mike's chili burger, perfect.
Why is the grilled cheese $54?
You got to really,
really want the grilled cheese.
Okay. It's a joke,
but trust me,
it ain't the grilled cheese
they're coming for.
I like Mike's chili
just a plain bowl of chili
with cheese and onions.
There's something
just magic about it.
I'm not sure what it is.
Phil won't tell us.
Because the recipe has been
a closely-guarded family secret
for 85 years.
Is it written down?
Not written down.
Not written down?
Not written down anywhere.
Instead, it's been passed down
from Mike's great-grandfather,
also named Mike.
Your grandfather,
your great-grandfather,
came here from Greece.
Right.
And, like a lot of Greeks,
he decides to start cooking.
So he's cooking
in a restaurant,
comes up with this
great chili recipe,
decides he wants to leave
and open his own restaurant.
FIERI:
In 1939, he built this place.
When you were 21, you and your
dad took it over together?
Right.
In '66,
Phil started
running the place himself.
Twenty years later, Mike
jumped in.
Suck it in, big guy.
Together, they're
proud to tell you
they've changed
virtually nothing...
Where are my crackers, Mike?
There we go.
Especially
what's in the bowl.
We don't make it with beans.
We don't make it
with anything else
that I've always kind
of called filler stuff.
Then we serve
it over beans.
I think that really is
what makes it special.
We just put the meat and
the secret spice recipe that my,
you know, great-grandfather
started in the '20s.
FIERI: It's also the all-day
cooking process
that starts with beef
stock, onions and garlic.
We didn't saute them. We just
throw everybody in the pool?
That's right.
Now the meat.
Okay, so mix, mix, mix...
Until it breaks down.
Until it all breaks down.
This is like your own
little athletic workout.
Do you want to arm wrestle?
Maybe. So we're making
what we're calling sauce?
We're making the sauce.
You see, our chili
and our beans,
they never get mixed together
unless you want them
together in a bowl.
Because true chili,
by most people's standards,
is meat only.
That's it.
This is how you've
always done it?
Always.
And with it all
right out in the open,
everyone can watch these guys
make it from scratch.
I think people would get
scared if they walk in
and they don't see
that pot cooking.
Yeah. That's true.
Sometimes they do.
After several hours
of simmering,
the sauce is finally ready
for the big bag of spices.
There's like 85 different
spices going on in there.
What is in this?
Oh, a whole bunch of stuff.
There's got to be
some chili powder...
That's what it is.
And oregano.
I don't think you have
any intention of telling me.
No. You're right.
No. Absolutely.
That's more than I've ever
done for anybody else.
For anybody else?
Hey, I'm Italian.
Greeks are almost Italians.
No. No.
So how much longer
is this going to hang out?
Well, actually,
just a little while now.
Be careful.
Why?
It's addicting?
Be careful.
He'll warn you.
That's the only bad thing
about this chili.
Mm, that's tasty.
Isn't it?
You guys should call this,
like, a chili parlor.
It'd be a good name.
While lots of folks go
for the basic bowl...
We got oyster crackers.
That's a must.
It's the chili combos
that will really spin
your head around.
My favorite way to eat Mike's
chili is in a chili burger,
right down the middle.
Feed a family.
Come on down to Mike's
Chili Parlor and...
Cheese first?
Yeah, cheese first.
All right. We're going onions.
That's a little soft
for a guy like you.
Okay. Now we're talking.
Now we're talking.
You want me to do the peppers
for you this time?
No.
You got it?
You've been ridiculous on all of
the other volume portions.
Is that enough?
I think it's perfect.
Okay.
Can someone really eat that?
Oh, yeah, definitely.
You want a deep breath,
take a deep breath or something?
That's a primo chili burger.
Nice spice to it.
It's very flavor...
The cheese melts really quick
because it's cut thin.
Yep.
Then you get the real meaty
texture of the patty.
Right.
Now, I don't know anybody
that can do a gourmet breakdown
on such thing as a chili burger,
but I got to tell you,
that burger is in it
to win it right there.
And if the burger
is not enough of a meal,
check out the chili pasta.
That's what I'm talking about.
Looks good, huh?
Looks good?
For you Italians,
that's the Italian chili.
Oh, yeah. No. This is where we
start getting into this.
I mean, I know
a few things...
About pasta?
What do you think about that?
You like that?
Because I like the
little jalapeno nuggets.
That's the kicker on this.
The food is great.
It feels like home.
Nothing beats Mike's.
FIERI: Because Mike's Chili
Parlor is still doing it
the way it's been done
since the beginning.
That's the stuff.
Isn't it nice to have
a place like this so close?
Beats the heck out of
all the fast food stuff.
Life is short.
What a better way
to spend a lot of it?
You know, you can't
create a place like this.
It has to happen over time.
This is my oldest customers.
We've been going here
for 37, 38...
They said...
You know what they just told me?
They said "We didn't
even know he served chili.
We just come in
for the abuse."
That's true.
Coming up,
talk about tradition.
That's what I was looking for.
We're headed to the oldest
family-run restaurant
in Vancouver...
This place is an institution.
Also known
as food coma central.
This kind young lady here
has been feeding me beef
six ways to Sunday.
♪♪
On triple D, we love
visiting the joints
that are part of history.
We're here in North Vancouver,
British Columbia,
about over the Lion's
Gate Bridge to check out a joint
that is the oldest family-run
restaurant in Vancouver.
This is the Tomahawk.
Steak and mushroom pie.
This place is an institution.
Beef dip.
It's where I grew up.
It's just become an icon.
Yorkshire pudding.
FIERI: And so is
second-generation owner,
Chuck Chamberlain...
-Chuck is the Tomahawk, period.
...who took over the joint
after his parents
opened it back in 1926.
MAN: When mom and dad started,
they had no idea on how to cook,
but it wasn't a restaurant.
It was more of a meeting
place at that time.
But today, folks come
for the food...
Eggs fill-up.
And that's all thanks
to Head Chef Ann Zubaidi...
Steak and mushroom pie, up.
Who cooked in restaurants
around the world
before moving to Canada.
Because I wanted to learn
Canadian cooking.
Eh. That's what you say,
right, "Eh?"
Eh. Eh.
And she brought
an English favorite
that people here go bananas for,
and, you know, bananas is good.
Yorkshire pudding.
Served alongside
their roast beef dinner.
What's your favorite
thing on the menu?
Beside the Yorkshire pudding?
I know it's going to
be good every time.
I've been waiting to make
Yorkshire pudding for years.
As my career
went on being a chef,
I had to make Yorkshire pudding.
I suck at making
Yorkshire pudding.
It just always has been, like,
really flat bread muffins
that don't taste good at all.
I am now your disciple.
So we have flour.
We've got four eggs,
and we give them a little whisk,
and then we're adding
milk and plain water.
We've got that mixed,
pinch of salt to the flour.
We start that whisking,
and we pour the liquid
in slowly, so...
Is this where
the magic happens?
This is when magic happens.
It mixes until it's not lumpy.
Okay. That's done,
and so we have our pan.
This is about 50 years old.
Well, this is going to be
leaving in a red Camaro.
If this is the magic muffin tin,
I'm taking it.
We're putting beef drippings in.
Beautiful.
This goes into the oven.
I've come to understand
a certain level of depression
when I've tried to do these,
and they have not come out
Puffy McMagic.
They've come out Flat McTragic.
I'm just going to
leave on that one.
So we've got Yorkshire
pudding, pan ready,
and it's going to sizzle.
Then they go back in the oven.
What temp are we at?
Four-hundred.
And they will be Puffy McMagic?
In about half an hour.
Next.
We're going to do
the roast beef,
so I make a little
scoring on the top,
and then we're going
to put grainy mustard,
Montreal steak spice,
and we just massage it in.
Roast off in the oven
at what temp?
Three-fifty, about
an hour and a half.
We've got the beef drippings.
Going to scrape
all this goodness
from the pan into my stock pot,
and we're bringing that up
to a nice sizzle, adding flour.
So we're making gravy?
We're making gravy.
Where did the au
jus come from?
We make our own beef stock.
We brown the bones.
Of course we brown the bones,
and we make dip from...
Ugh. Look how dark and rich
and beautiful that is.
That's the back
of the Camaro too.
It's doing its thickening,
and it's done.
Okay.
Here, Yorkshire puddings.
Okay. Here we go.
Are you guys ready for this?
Watch.
There we go.
That's what I'm looking for.
Absolutely not how mine look.
Quickly, they're puffing down!
Now do we start
slicing meat?
Would you like the big one?
Beautiful gravy
over everything.
Two knives and forks...
Go ahead.
Oh. That's outstanding.
I haven't had that
puffy type of Yorkshire
pudding in 20-some years.
On the homemade mashed potatoes
with the Yorkshire pudding,
a little of
the whole-grain mustard,
and then you get that really
tender puff from the pastry.
It's really...
More gravy, please.
For you, anything.
♪♪
Fantastic job.
Thank you.
That's what I was looking for.
Roast beef dinner.
The Yorkshire pudding...
I won't try anybody else's.
This is perfect.
Roast beef dinner,
it's very tender.
It honestly reminds me of Mom's.
You know the only thing
wrong with Yorkshire pudding?
Tell me.
It eventually runs out.
Plus, they've got to save
some of that beef
for their biggest seller.
Beef dip!
Beef dip.
I am having the beef dip.
It is very good.
FIERI: But if you're from
the lower 48,
you might know it as French dip
or a dry dip sandwich.
♪♪
There's so many things
that make this so right.
The bread, perfect,
great crunch.
The meat was roasted with
that whole-grain mustard
which you really
taste the meat.
What's that over there?
Use this to wipe my face.
Beef dip.
The meat is extremely tender,
and the gravy is delicious.
This kind young lady, here,
has been feeding me beef
six ways to Sunday.
We have had
the Yorkshire pudding.
We've had the beef dip
with beef au jus,
and now guess what
we're going to have?
Steak and mushroom
pie with gravy.
Absolutely, we are,
and I'm going to push
the car back
over the big bridge
that I got here on.
How do we start this?
The pie dough for the
pot pie shell.
Start it off.
All-purpose flour
goes into our big mixer,
salt and baking powder,
shortening, all vegetable.
Nothing is short about that.
This is a 100-year-old recipe.
Ah, okay then.
That's like an extra
14 hours at the gym.
We're going to speed
it up a little bit.
Making some gravel.
We're making gravel.
That's right.
And you said this
recipe is how old?
Over 100 years.
Chuck is the owner,
and his mom and dad
started the Tomahawk in 1926.
Now, we add water,
and we bring it together.
And there. It's done.
It comes out of the bowl
to rest for an hour.
We roll it out, form it.
♪♪
We blind bake it with an egg
wash so they're nice and golden,
and we blind bake
the lids separately.
♪♪
This is a boat going to
Flavortown, right there.
Then we make the steak
and mushroom pie filling.
We've got the butter melting
with the garlic in it.
We've got the nice
happy steak.
We're going to put the steak
into the garlic butter,
a little cracked black pepper.
That's easy for you to say.
Yeah, not really.
A little salt...
All that's going to go in there?
More or less.
Well, it's either more
or it's less.
Definitely more because it's
going to flow over the sides.
Mushrooms...
And, of course, you're going
to take those to Gravytown.
Gravytown.
Oh, see. This is awesome.
So we cook all the steak,
all the mushrooms.
All the flavors
are coming together.
I feel like I'm in, like,
prayer meditation,
the way you're saying,
"All the steak,
all the mushrooms."
Well, that's what it feels like.
"All the gravy
is coming together."
Somebody play
the didgeridoo right now.
[ Imitating digeridoo ]
Okay, and then this
is ready to serve.
We love to stack it high,
and then to plate it.
There we go.
That's how it comes out.
It looks too pretty
to break into.
♪♪
That flaky crust is just
soaking up the gravy.
Here's what makes it:
the mushrooms,
the scratch-made gravy,
the copious amounts of
shortening all put together,
and the tender beef.
It's comfort food.
It's a hundred-year-old
recipe, excellent job.
Thank you.
You rocked it.
You are the beefinator.
Steak and mushroom pie, up.
Lots of steak, lots of
mushrooms, and the rich gravy.
It's very good.
It's like a piece of bread
that comes on top.
Works perfectly as you
crumble it into the meat itself.
It's exactly the Tomahawk taste
that I love which
is home cooking.
We love to have
our community restaurants,
but one that's been
around this long,
to be the longest family-run
restaurant in Vancouver...
Right.
...since 1926.
1926, right.
Amazing, congratulations.
Well, thank you very much.
Thanks for having us.
Thanks, Guy.
Thanks for being here.
Up next, in Chicago... I'm out!
...a family cooking up
old-school Italian...
I'm going to do damage on this.
...since the 1930s.
I'm expecting magic.
You'll get it.
All right.
So get this, right after
Herbert Hoover is elected
President, an Italian immigrant
by the name of Joe DiBuono
takes over Tufano's Bar here in
Chicago's Little Italy.
Well, he and his wife start
cooking up classic
Italian dishes out of
their house next door.
Three generations later,
the family is still running it,
and the place is so well-known,
well, hey.
They don't even need a sign.
-Thanks for coming in.
-We love Joey.
-That's Joey DiBuono III.
-You guys okay?
Carrying on
the family tradition.
Walking in here is like
walking in at home.
Everybody knows about it?
Everyone knows about it.
Place to be if you want family-
style, authentic Italian food.
Yeah. That's what this place is,
is a family restaurant.
FIERI: Always has been,
and now Joey...
Rigatonis...
is running it with his family.
His daughters...
Alfredo sauce?
Your twin daughters,
are they going to take over?
Yeah. They're very personable.
They're very good.
They're aware of things.
Those two running this house,
oh, my goodness.
That's special for you,
though, right?
And they'll still be serving up
the red sauce classics...
-The meatballs.
-The stuffed shells.
Can I get a gallon
of that to go?
And all the other
family favorites.
You know, you don't have
to make it complicated.
Simple flavors,
but nice, big taste.
Picate with some angel hair.
The flavor is in the food.
-The mussels are very good.
-The pork chops?
Lemon chicken is the
best thing they serve.
I heard the lemon chicken is
supposed to be your specialty,
and the bomb.
Everybody really loves it.
Get a whole chicken.
Put a little cooking oil
in there, a touch of olive oil,
and I get some fresh garlic,
pepper, a little salt,
a little oregano,
and then you get
a freshly whole lemon,
and you just squeeze
it right in there.
Look at that thing,
like a Vise-Grip.
He'll be taking rocks and making
rock juice out of it
in a second.
And this just goes
in the boiler.
How long are we
going to go down?
With this heat,
it cooks in 15 minutes.
I'm expecting magic.
You'll get it.
All right.
And then we use potatoes.
Cottage fries, and this is
what comes alongside it?
Uh-huh.
Is the big bird ready?
It's ready.
Look at the way that's roasted
down like that.
Really holds in the juices.
Just take a few of the potatoes.
Add it to the chicken,
and we sprinkle it with the oil,
and it gives it
a great taste.
And that's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
Want to arm wrestle
for the thigh?
I don't want to embarrass
you on the camera.
Look at that.
Melts in your mouth,
super crispy.
Now, I get a little
bit of the lemon,
definitely picking up
some of the oregano.
Look at that breast meat right
there, nice and super juicy.
I'm starting to understand,
Joey, why you're so popular.
We'll, I'm going to tell you,
that is some
bodacious bird, brother.
That's triple B on triple D.
I could eat that whole bird.
You're doing a pretty
good job, there.
I know!
Well done on the outside
and very tender on the inside.
-It's spicy.
-It's juice.
It's one of my favorites, here.
It's a wonderful
dish, delicious.
Something I've been
having here for 25 years.
Can't forget where you came from
and what's worked for
you all these years.
You think you have enough?
FIERI:
The Italian family cooking
has become a local legend.
All right. Thank you.
My parents grew up here.
My grandparents...
I was brought here as a kid.
My ma has been coming
here for 60 years.
How long have you been
coming here?
-Seventeen years.
-Twelve or thirteen years.
Shells, broccoli and shrimp.
We always come back here,
the old favorite.
They remember you
when you come in.
-Just for you, Mike.
-They talk to you.
Is it all right here so far?
Oh, excellent, excellent.
How does it feel to be a legacy
in Italian food in Chicago?
I'm honored. I'm honored that
my grandma and grandpa
were able to start this.
It's a great tradition.
A lot of people come here
from all over the country.
Let's talk about
who is on the wall.
Dick Vitale, Phil Jackson,
Bob Costas.
Who's this cat?
Rocky Marciano.
And this was my grandpa, here.
And making everyone feel at home
is a family tradition
Joey is proud to carry on...
How are you doing there?
with food straight from
his grandparents' kitchen...
We got in the meatball?
right down to the tomato
sauce grandma called red gravy.
This is the way
we were brought up.
This is what my grandma
and my grandpa taught us.
Sausage, I see.
Beef, couple pieces of pork too.
We got neck bones.
Neck bones?
That doesn't look like
any rib right there.
So you get a bunch
of marrow out of there.
You got to get a ton
of flavor out of that.
Everybody in the pool.
Saporito tomatoes,
add a little basil to it.
And then you just let it go down
for about 3 1/2 hours.
How about you do the rest
of the show by yourself,
and I'll watch this?
Look at that, just getting
it going right here.
I have a thing
about gravy, tomato sauce,
and that is just make it right.
Just make it righteous,
and, my friend,
mm, this is right and righteous.
For that, you get a hug.
I get a...
Their sauce is
out of this world.
FIERI: Whatever it's on,
the mostaccioli,
the eggplant parm,
and this heavy hitter.
Chicken parm.
Thank you.
Look at that.
Mm, winner.
Is this their big order?
I've tried the chicken.
I've tried the raviolis.
I get the rigatoni.
The meatballs, pretty much
everything is real good.
-Fried calamari.
-Shells and broccoli.
Veal picante.
Veal picante?
Joey says this one
is a newcomer, his own recipe,
on the menu only 10 years.
Bring it on.
-Inside round...
You do the veal top round
and everything here?
Yeah. We trim it,
and we cut it ourselves.
That's old-school. Tenderize it
a little bit, now we're talking.
Put them in the flour...
Straight egg wash.
And the bread crumbs.
I use the white bread crumbs.
I don't use the regular,
hard bread crumbs.
That's what makes it so good.
Start with a little butter,
and the veal doesn't take
too long to cook.
No, it doesn't.
I use a little lemon juice.
A little chicken stock,
and that's all she wrote.
That's a nice portion.
Sprinkle a little juice
on there, pine nuts.
Yeah. That's a
nice-looking round.
There's tons of flavor in that.
Mm, I could do damage on this.
Super tender,
it's nice and light.
You know what that is?
That's a real deal Holy-veal.
♪♪
I'll be here all week.
You should try the veal.
Don't forget to
tip your waitress.
How many years I've
wanted to use that line,
and it finally worked.
I'm out!
Veal is the best in the city,
almost melts in your mouth.
-It's very good.
-Everything is good, fresh.
-Here's your bruschetta.
-It couldn't be done any better.
Bon appetit.
It's just a family place.
You can tell a lot of love
was put into this.
You've got to love what you're
doing. Jill, pick up.
And that's what do here.
It tastes like homemade cooking.
There's the dough
with the vodka sauce.
There's nothing
more you can ask for.
This is the best
Italian restaurant
in the city of
Chicago, bar none.
Joey, I can see why everybody
from the aunts to your mom,
your wife to your daughters,
why everybody loves Joey.
Yeah.
Coming up on this full hour
of family-owned treasures...
I like the way
this is looking, boss.
A sibling-run standout
in Jersey City...
Just shovel it in.
Shovel.
Where pancakes are
the star of the show.
That is, like, adult warm
strawberry shortcake.
You know, you can find
an average pancake
just about anywhere,
but finding a really
killer pancake,
well, that's a
whole another deal,
and that's why I'm in
Jersey City, New Jersey,
at this family-owned
joint that's doing them right,
doing them right
31 different ways.
-Honky-tonk pancakes.
-Cran-apple pancake.
Meat pancake.
-Oh, my goodness.
-Beautiful, guys.
Nutty pancakes,
berry pancakes.
That's a winner, winner
chicken dinner right there.
They're awesome.
Throw in just about anything
else you could ask for...
They make a killer breakfast.
And you've got
the Brownstone Diner,
a one-stop breakfast shop
they're lining up for.
It's always crowded.
And whole-wheat toast?
Exactly.
Let's rock.
It's a tradition
the Bournias family
has kept going for
more than 40 years.
You guys ready?
Follow me.
The first generation
came here from Greece.
My mom came here with
her father and siblings.
There you go.
Thank you.
The kids all started out
in different professions...
All right, Debbie.
...but couldn't stay away.
We all wanted to work
as a family again.
I wanted to keep
the tradition going.
WOMAN: I love working
with my family.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
FIERI: Neither would the folks
lining up for their
killer pancakes.
Now, who did this
recipe come from?
It's my father's.
I don't know that I've ever seen
a 5-gallon bucket of buttermilk.
Vegetable oil...
Yep.
We do another gallon of eggs.
It gets a little messy.
I got to say flour
comes in at some point.
And we just do pretty much
six containers of this.
Yeah. You keep it
scientific.
That's three.
That was four.
Here is six.
Okay. That's going to be seven.
This will be seven.
And that's pretty much it.
And that's...
I think you owe one more.
Huh? We got one more to go?
Man, you're throwing
off my count.
We just add
a touch of vanilla syrup.
The secret ingredient
is in here.
You're hiding it
in confectionery sugar?
How long will the batter
last, for a day or two?
Our batters are
only for that day.
This size, we do about
12 on the weekend.
What, did they give me
the Easy-Bake Oven spatula?
That's how we do it.
Berry, meat, honky-tonk.
Want to make those?
Yeah. I'll even give you
a nut and honey.
That's another big
favorite, if you'd like.
Nut and honey.
And you see the way
this batter is nice and thick?
It's going to give
it a nice texture.
Before we put the toppings,
I just want it to cook
just a little bit,
just to kind of create
that little pearl.
Now, this is specifically
just the pancake section?
There is nothing on
this grill but pancakes.
If you're going to call
yourself Pancake Factory,
you better have a precisionially
-tuned griddle just for this.
Griddle, that's it.
This is the meat pancake?
Fresh bacon, cooked,
just throw that right there.
The nut is almonds,
some walnuts.
The honey goes at the end.
For the honky-tonk, these are
peanut butter, really good.
You see the way it's
getting that nice height?
Right. Right.
Now, how do you know
which one is which?
We're going to have
to turn them over.
Now, you would get, seriously,
on an order you would get
three nutty like that?
Yeah. Nuts and honey, just do
a little powdered sugar.
Just shovel it in.
Oh, I -- Shovel?
Just shovel it, yeah.
It's my middle name.
Mm, I would order
that pancake.
How does this
pancake stack up?
Get it?
Actually, it's awesome.
And this is our honky-tonk.
Good peanut butter flavor,
I like that the banana
goes on not-hot.
They're nice. They're fluffy.
They're always fresh.
This one, hot
strawberry preserves.
And we just take
a dab of sour cream.
Whoa!
You got, like, that hot-cold.
♪♪
That is, like, adult warm
strawberry shortcake.
You still got more to go.
Oh. This is the meat pancake.
Excuse me?
Can I get some
ketchup and hot sauce?
On the pancake?
♪♪
That's good, right?
That's what I'm talking
about, right there!
The locals have been talking
about these pancakes
and a whole lot more...
The food is delicious.
for more than 40 years.
Brownstone deluxe.
Eat the onion rings first
and then the burger.
FIERI: But, with this menu,
you're never too far from
a pancake.
It's the country pancake wrap.
It's like an oversized pancake,
and we wrap
different stuff in it.
Like pigs in the
blanket gone wild?
Yeah. We got some eggs,
potatoes, sausage, some cheese.
Called a pancake
burrito, pancake gyro.
That's good.
You said gyro.
A lot of people say "jai-roh,"
but "yee-roh," that's...
It's not my first
pancake rodeo.
Wow. Look at that profile.
You got that sweet
and salty and the egg.
All the flavor
inside the pancake.
I'm telling you,
savory pancakes.
They have a lot of different
pancake wraps here,
and it works though.
It tastes really good.
-Can I make one?
-Yeah.
Pancake wrap,
Northern California style.
My parents encouraged me
to play with my food.
Breaking apart, captain!
Oh, there you go.
How about any blue cheese?
♪♪
That's what I'm talking about.
Wow.
You put on spicy buffalo
pancake on that menu,
there's someone is
going to try it.
Man, that is really good.
I haven't come here yet and had
anything that I didn't like.
We just love it.
It's really great.
I wake up on Saturday morning,
and this is what I think about.
My dad would see
people pull up,
and he'd start making
their pancakes
because he knew what they were
going to get every single day.
FIERI: But dad's also
famous around here
for cooking up
the family favorites
he grew up with
back in Greece.
-Moussaka is very authentic.
-Delicious.
-So what do we do first?
-Saute the onions.
What else we got in here?
We got some dill...
Parsley.
Italian parsley.
Okay.
Put a little olive oil.
I like your measuring technique.
A little bit of white wine.
Yeah.
But why is it in the glass
I've been seeing you
drink out of all morning?
That's what I do all day.
Okay. I like it.
Put in the ground beef, now.
For the diced tomatoes...
Yeah. I put a little of
the flour, tomato paste.
Looks good.
You can put in the potatoes.
We're going to put
in the potatoes.
That splashing oil
doesn't bother you, does it?
Nah.
Do we cut some eggplant?
What temperature, 350?
Yeah.
For...
About 20 minutes.
And layer it all up
like a Greek lasagna.
A little zing, eggplant.
Oh, nice and crispy.
I like the way
this is looking, boss.
Parmesan cheese.
And a scratch-made
bechamel sauce.
Still do it.
Okay. I'll still do it.
Let's put it in the oven, now.
For how long?
About 1 hour.
Oh, look at that.
Look good, eh?
Okay, Guy.
Is this for two?
No. It's for one.
Creamy, it's rich.
Just take a look at that,
the cream sauce on top,
the bechamel, really nice.
I think I see why
it's so popular.
And I thought it was
just a pancake factory.
Not that there's
anything wrong with that.
The pancakes are really thick
and, like, cake-like.
It's awesome.
I like the fact that I can
get breakfast 24 hours a day.
You know, I just love the place.
Is this what you all thought the
diner business was going to be?
We anticipated the long hours,
but it's a lot of fun.
All right, Lewis.
I'm going to scream over there.
I do that pretty well.
I have a lot of fun.
You're going to come
to work tomorrow?
That's fantastic. Thank you.
It'd be nice if my dad had,
like, a dozen kids
so we could split
the shifts a little bit.
-Should have had more kids.
-"Should have had more kids?"
We've gone to pancakes
to wraps, and look.
There's so many more chapters,
but that is all
for this reading, today,
as the Brownstone turns.
Up next, in Santa Fe...
That's money, dude.
A husband and wife dishing
out rockstar rellenos...
I'm a huge fan of that.
And pupusas with a punch.
You have completely
train-wrecked me, man.
I'm rolling through
Santa Fe, New Mexico,
and I'm taking you
to a little joint
that's probably like
a perfect example
of what we're looking
for here on triple D.
It's owned by a
husband-and-wife team.
They're scratch cooking
just about everything.
The place is just
full of character,
and the neighborhood
totally digs it.
You got to check out
Tune-Up Cafe.
-You have the tamale in there.
-This is a very local spot.
-It's in my neighborhood.
-What do we got?
FIERI: Run by a couple...
I'll be back.
From the neighborhood.
We live down the street.
Adam.
It feels like home.
FIERI: El Salvador native,
Jesus Rivera...
Corn tortilla.
...and his wife, Charlotte,
bought this place
less than a year ago.
Jesus was working at two
restaurants at the same time,
and I thought,
if he's working that hard,
he should have his own place.
So now he's cranking
out comfort food...
Stuffed French toast has
a little bit of cream cheese.
-Southwestern favorites...
-The chile rellenos...
Chili pepper stuffed
with cheese.
-Delicious.
-Pupusas.
FIERI: And this El Salvadoran
dish Jesus grew up with.
Cornmeal stuffed with flank
steak, corn and green chilies.
It starts out very mild, and
then there's a burst of flavor.
This is going
to be the beef
that is going to
go in the pupusa?
Yeah.
Okay. So now a little bit
of oil down?
Yeah.
So you saute the onions
down a little bit?
Yeah. And next, garlic.
Okay. So those are sauteed
for 10 minutes.
Now what?
This is the flank steak.
Wow. We're making a lot.
Yeah. I love flank steak, too.
So that'll all brown up.
Now it's time for the
tomatoes and the peppers.
Chile pasado.
Yeah, salt and pepper.
So then, cook all that up?
Oh. I can't wait to try this.
How long is it going to take?
One hour is enough.
I don't think that
I've ever had pupusa.
Okay. Only one?
All right. Okay.
Masa, salt, oil, water.
So, masa.
Masa.
Just like we
make a tortilla with.
Tortilla masa.
Okay.
This is for you.
It's how he did it.
Next.
Jesus, my brother,
they have these things
called tortilla press.
I'm going to get you
one for your birthday.
Okay.
Okay?
I do like the method, though.
We're making a thicker-than-an-
average tortilla.
You don't skimp
on the portions.
You give a lot.
Yeah, enough.
Next is corn,
Monterey cheese.
Monterey Jack cheese...
Yeah.
With the El Salvadorean dish?
Yeah. Okay.
This is for you.
Start it right here.
Little bit of corn.
You're doing good.
Okay. I'm all right, so far?
Yeah.
I'm graduating here
at the Tune-up Culinary
Education Center?
Now what happens?
Fold the pusa.
Put it in the middle like that.
All right.
So that's why you don't
use the tortilla press
because you've got to
have them on the paper.
You want to just kind of
make it into a round patty.
I wrap this in tin foil,
and I could cook it on the
manifold of my '67 out there.
Look at that!
We cook the pupusa with oil.
We don't want the heat too high.
We don't want it to brown
too fast without cooking.
Yeah.
So now we flip them over.
Like this.
Oh. Like this.
Perfect. Look.
This is the cheese
melting inside.
Uh-huh. I can see it.
This is ready.
Let's go putting
tomato sauce on top.
The roasted tomato sauce
of salt and pepper,
onions, jalapenos,
cilantro and the garlic.
Look at that!
Try it.
Crazy good.
If the meat wasn't
good enough just by itself,
the crispy, crunchy masa
on the outside with the corn
and the cheese oozing out of it.
That does it.
You guys completely
train-wrecked me, man.
That's awesome, man, seriously.
It's nice and crispy,
crunchy on the outside.
Really light,
has a different flavor
than anything else that
I've eaten here in town.
Oh. That's me.
FIERI: And the locals
just can't get enough of it.
I'm here a couple times a week.
Sometimes I've eaten
here twice a day.
There you go.
The food
is fabulous every time.
That's great, yeah.
And everybody is just having
a great time being here.
It feels so comfortable.
You can sit at the community
table, and meet new people.
Get whatever you're looking for.
Make me a banana leaf tamale.
Wow. This is crazy tasty.
-Fish tacos.
-Watermelon gazpacho.
Oh, is it good.
-A relleno?
FIERI: Even the classics
get a tune-up twist.
The chile relleno is
a common dish in Santa Fe,
but here it's different.
-Amazing.
They're so lightly breaded,
and it really brings out
the chile flavor.
So we're going to
take the Anaheims,
and this is going to be
for our chile rellenos?
Yeah, chile rellenos.
We're not
going to put anything on them?
Just throw it on the grill?
Light them up.
Let them roast, and when they
get done, you'll sweat them.
They cool down.
Now you take the skin off?
So now I just give it
a little tear into there?
Pull the seeds out
as much as you can.
We're making
a little pocket, here.
We add onions and cheese.
Monterey Jack cheese,
this is all mixed together?
Make a little
cheese torpedo.
Well, frankly, I don't...
Okay, so now...
Put the cheese inside the chile.
Look at that.
You got it.
So we got it done.
We put in the freezer...
Really?
for 20 minutes
until they're firm.
Now we make the batter?
The batter, yeah.
We separate the eggs.
Okay. So we got
all the whites in.
When this is plopping,
I put in the egg yolks, flour.
This is going to become
a really nice,
light batter on
the outside of this.
I'll mix by hand. Yeah.
Okay. So now we grab all of this
and go over here and fry them?
You need a little flour so
the batter will stick to them.
Now it's ready.
Wow.
Those go fast, huh?
Yeah.
Look at those. Beautiful, baby.
So they're done.
Now, how do we make a plate?
So a little bit of
the roasted tomato salsa,
cheese, put a little melt on it.
Look at that!
Refritos, the tortilla, here.
And that's how she comes?
With the cheeses oozing out like
lava over in Flavortown Volcano.
Got issues...
Mm. Mmm!
That's money, dude.
I'm going to tell you something.
I've never been that much
of a chile relleno fan,
typically because
the batter is too eggy.
This is light
and creamy and tender.
I mean, just cut it
with a fork and...
On point.
I'm a huge fan of that.
The rellenos are excellent.
It's nice and spicy.
It's like, "Woo!"
Inside, the cheese is just
oozing and it's delicious.
This is the place to come
for fantastic food.
Burrito, red.
Someone who's happy
and loves making food,
it comes out in the taste.
This is the American
dream, right here,
and look at you doing it now,
but I'll tell you something.
This guy is a working
machine, isn't he?
There's none better.
I think you might want
to think about expanding.
A few walls are going
to need to be pushed out.
You got to come check it out.
I'm not kidding you.
Coming up, in Roy, Utah...
He is in the zone.
A three-generation
burger sensation...
Is that how you roll?
Serving up the standards...
Look at that.
And some surprises.
Let's try the elk.
Okay.
So I'm kicking it
here in Roy, Utah.
Now, Salt Lake City is,
like, 35 miles that way.
Fifteen miles that way,
some killer skiing,
but for a lot of people,
this is the destination.
A little burger joint
that's been doing it
right for over 52 years.
You got to check out
the Burger Bar.
Two singles and a double.
Small fry, please.
There you go.
You can't get a burger that
tastes like this anywhere else.
It's big, and it's
got a lot of meat.
And I need that
burger pretty quick.
FIERI: The single is
a quarter-pound,
and they'll stack them.
Three double cheeseburgers.
from double to quad,
and even bigger.
Look at that, huh?
That's a good burger.
And all the other
drive-in classics.
Can you get me a foot-long?
The onion rings are my favorite.
Definitely the fries,
they're delicious.
FIERI: And all served up
with a Utah favorite.
Would you like extra fry sauce?
It's amazing, but fry sauce
goes with anything.
We make it with salad dressing
and ketchup.
Where we come from,
we call this thousand island.
But around here,
it's fry sauce.
Good old Utah
with our fry sauce.
A local favorite,
like the Burger Bar itself.
Now, how long have
you been coming here?
A few years.
It's been here a long time.
I think it's tradition.
I built it myself.
And I was working
with the baby on my back.
Ben and Rita Fowler
opened the joint in '56...
Did you want sauce
with your fry?
and the next two generations
followed them into the business.
Thank you.
So everybody has worked here?
Everybody.
We had to.
It was the family farm.
You got to chip in.
There you go.
Hi. May I help you?
It's a family place,
and we take pride in it.
Of the siblings that work here,
you're kind of...
I'm the top dog.
You're top dog.
That's correct.
And Jessica's top job
is keeping everything the way
everyone expects it to be.
Here you go, Brent.
Everything is so fresh.
It's better than
any fast food joint.
Are they shake-shakes
or they kind of puny shakes?
-They're big.
-About that much over the rim.
No kidding?
Everyone likes it.
Especially their
signature burger...
I want a cheese Ben.
The quarter-pounder
called the Big Ben.
It's just a great hamburger.
The Ben is our
speciality hamburger.
It's named after my grandfather.
What is that?
This is
our round-sliced bacon...
Round-sliced bacon,
and where's the meat come from?
They grind the meat daily.
So it's never frozen?
No. And we like to put our
cheese on so it's melted,
and we toast our bun.
All right. Come over here.
You want to add
the fry sauce?
Oh. Do it the way
you normally do it.
All right.
We have our pickle.
Throw some tomato on there.
Big burger.
That's great.
And then, in the summer months,
those tomatoes
come out of our garden.
The burger is really juicy.
The bacon is money.
The cheese melts nice,
and then the fry sauce...
You know, the thing that ties
it all together is that bun.
My favorite part is
the homemade Ben bun.
Gosh. That's really good.
Do single, we can do double.
We can go up to triples
and quads, too.
The cheese Ben
and the quad burgers
are what we've been eating.
That's a full pound of beef, but
it's nothing to this cat, Tyler.
We've got the record of eating
the biggest burger here?
Yes. I do.
How many?
Twelve patties.
Twelve patties?
How long'd it take you.
Hour and 5 minutes.
But today, he's cutting back,
just going for eight.
You want to wrap this?
I don't even think
I could sing about it.
Oh, and we got some
cheese on there, too.
Well, cheese and some of
the sauce.
Where's your cheering crew?
Oh. My wife is right over there.
Are you condoning
this behavior?
Absolutely.
You think your daddy
can eat all of that?
-Yes.
-How long?
Forty minutes.
Go!
Okay.
That's a good burger.
We'll check back a little later
and see how he's doing
with the big beef.
He's in the zone.
He is in the zone.
But it's not just beef here.
We need two buffalo burgers.
Two buffalo!
Our exotic meats
are buffalo and our elk.
Like, real buffalo?
Yeah.
Usually put a lid on it just to
kind of keep the moisture in it
so it doesn't dry out.
All right. Go with
the fry sauce, again.
At least you don't
hold back on that.
I'll take a bite.
I think I like the buffalo
better than the regular.
Do you?
Yeah. It's got a meatier flavor.
It's got great texture.
That's good.
It really is good.
I'd say it's a lot better
than just a normal hamburger,
a little bit leaner.
We have fans of the buffalo,
and we have fans of the elk.
I am having the
elk burger today.
Let's try the elk.
Okay.
And where does
the elk come from?
Utah elk, gourmet elk.
Do you eat a lot
of the elk burger?
Uh-huh.
So I think this I want to do
just a little bit of sauce on.
Light?
I don't want... Oh.
There is such a thing.
Man, that's good.
You like it?
It's less than
2 grams of fat, so...
Seriously?
Seriously.
Not gamey, got great flavor,
incredible texture, excellent.
It's just a nice
break from beef.
-And speaking of beef...
-I feel pretty good.
Remember Tyler, who's
slamming an eight-patty burger?
He's not done yet.
So while Tyler is
trying to finish,
we'll check out what
he's having on the side.
Can I get a Ben fry, please?
Definitely the fries.
They're delicious.
You can even get
them triple-fried.
Fry them once in the morning?
Uh-huh. We blanch them
just for a minute,
just do, like,
part of the cooking,
and so it'll cook up
faster and more crisp.
Now, how long will
they go down now?
These will go down
for 2 minutes.
So they'll go for 2 minutes.
Then what happens?
Then you pull them out?
And we pull them up,
and we let them actually...
Rest again.
Right, and then
drop them back down
when they're ready to go out,
and they stay crispy
for a lot longer.
That has great crunch.
Excellent fries.
Same with the rings.
The onion rings
are fantastic.
You can tell they
make them by hand.
Any particular type of onion
that we're working with?
The yellow onion, these have
been soaked overnight.
We put them just
in our flour, here.
Give it a little shake
off the excess,
and then we put buttermilk.
We just put this over here
in our cracker, coat it.
These are our onion rings.
This is the boat
we'll use to put them in.
That's your measuring system?
Yeah.
How long?
About 2, 3 minutes.
That about done?
Yep.
Look at that.
Crispy, crunchy, excellent.
That fry sauce, that's...
Money?
You like it?
You just throw out "Money?"
I don't know.
Is that how you roll?
That's how I roll.
They're handmade, and so you
can tell they're fresh.
FIERI: So are the huge shakes.
Here's your Butterfinger
and your raspberry.
That's why I come here,
is the milkshakes.
FIERI: And they're doing a local
take on a lime rickey.
Grape, lime and Sprite.
That's refreshing.
But it is the Burger Bar.
You want to go
for another eight?
And how's my buddy Tyler doing?
One bite for the rest of it?
Okay. Are you ready?
[ LAUGHS ]
Look at that!
And after predicting
40 minutes...
What was the time on it?
...he did it in less than 15.
I got to tell you, man,
fair and square, baby.
What do you think?
He didn't do bad.
Making Roy, Utah, proud.
Jump. I got you.
So was this a great
road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives."
You have to wait
for something good.
Look. See if they're ready.
No peeking.
Set your watch, Mr. Bling.
♪♪