Hey, I'm Guy Fieri.
And you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown!
This is "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
This trip...
I feel like
I walked into a fiesta.
That's because we're
cruising the states
for some south of the border.
My mouth is watering.
From Florida to California...
Authentic, baby.
...Southwest to Midwest...
That's money.
...we've got tacos
and tamales...
If there was a county
in Flavortown named tamale,
that would be it.
...al pastor and posole...
You're gonna love this.
...all the favorites...
But I've got to tell you,
chef, it is delicious.
...plus some new discoveries.
Never seen it. I've been eating
Mexican food all my life.
So get ready for this full
hour of Mexican to the max.
Oh, that's fantastic.
That's all right here,
right now on "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here
in Richfield, Minnesota,
about 10 minutes
from downtown Minneapolis.
Now, this is a great place
to come to.
One, a bunch of my "Triple D"
crew lives here.
Two, they have got
an eclectic mix of restaurants.
But I got to be honest with you,
when my crew tells me
they've got a real-deal
Mexican joint in Minnesota,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Andale.
You can't get this kind
of authentic Mexican
anywhere in the Twin Cities.
RANGEL: Sopa de mariscos.
It's like walking into
a little cafe in Mexico.
FIERI: And much more because
when Fernando Mellado
and Jorge Rangel opened in 2011,
they went for,
pardon the expression,
the whole enchilada.
One side is full-blown
restaurant...
-Right.
-...and, I mean, huge menu.
The other side is market.
You got a butcher shop.
You have a bakery.
-Right, right.
We get a lot of people coming
in here for the restaurant
and then come
and explore the market.
So that's a big deal.
MAN:
You can come every meal
and go right next door
and get some groceries,
go home and try
and re-create your own meal.
RANGEL: Three tacos pastor.
The al pastor tacos
are like getting street tacos.
They're super fresh
with the nice cilantro taste
and the crispy onions.
What are we into now?
We're gonna make the al
pastor sauce for the tacos.
Got it.
We're gonna start
with a guajillo pepper,
orange juice,
lime juice, cumin,
black pepper,
bay leaves, oregano.
Mexican oregano is nice,
big, super-bold flavor.
Achiote.
This is the annatto seed
that's made into a paste,
but there's also
flavors in this.
Okay.
Garlic, onions,
salt, white vinegar.
And then, we use
the big blender right here.
Don't get this on me.
I only have one
Spiritual Gangster shirt.
Okay. So we take
the sliced pork.
We put it in there,
and how long will it marinate?
-For 24 hours.
-Next up?
We're gonna do
the salsa verde right here.
We have
the boiled jalapeños,
garlic,
the onions, the salt,
avocados and use
the immersion blender.
Go ahead and start
pouring the oil. Slow.
How is that?
That's fantastic.
Next thing we're gonna do,
we're gonna make our tacos.
On the flat top,
a little bit of oil,
dropped some onions.
-And a little bit of bacon.
-A little bit of bacon, too.
Yeah, and pineapple.
All gonna cook together.
We do, like,
a double tortilla.
How many do I get, 12?
-Three. Three.
-Three.
-Three works for me.
-Okay.
So we got
the al pastor tacos.
Okay.
Cilantro, onions...
a little lime juice.
-Okay.
Here is the avocado
salsa that we made.
♪♪
Let's see
what you think.
♪♪
There is no way
we're in Minnesota,
no way.
The meat,
perfectly marinated.
It's got a nice crisp to it,
right amount of onion.
Tortillas are charred.
The salsa is outstanding.
-You're making me hungry.
-I'm gonna tell you what.
The way you cook,
the discipline, scratch-made...
I mean, they scratch-make
just everything.
Outstanding, Chef.
-Thank you.
-Nice job, buddy.
-Wow.
-The pork had lots of flavor.
It's really tender and juicy.
The salsa verde had
a lot of kick to it
from the jalapeños.
MAN #2: Everything they make
here is fresh.
I mean, they have
their own butcher here.
They process their own meat.
-Torta ranchera.
MAN #3: Well, there's obviously
some very knowledgeable people
who prepare this food
because it's done very well.
FIERI: So well that
my Minnesota-based crew
gives it huge props.
We get off the plane
in Minneapolis
and head straight here
because it's the taste
of home for us.
It's just like the tacos
we had when we were all down
in Mexico together.
The al pastor,
off the hook,
and now we're making...
-The carnitas.
We're making carnitas
for tamales,
and the hood is on
because this is smoking.
This is hot, and you've got
to have this cauldron
to make this happen.
We're gonna start
with curing the meat.
And what kind of fat
are we using?
-Lard.
-We're using lard.
So now
we've seared it all off.
Cola.
You got to do a little cola,
you know why?
Color.
Cinnamon,
oranges and salt.
We're gonna put
the pork stomachs in there.
Boy, I hope they're not out
of pork stomach today,
when I go to Andale.
We're gonna cover it
with the pork skin.
-More lard.
-Yeah.
Yeah, this is awesome.
A hot tub of pig.
-Okay.
And we're gonna let it
cook for 6 hours.
How often do you make
this much carnitas?
-We make every day.
-Every day, this much?
Every day,
this much, yes.
The carnitas are ready.
Now we're gonna pull them
and shred them.
We've got the masa.
And what is the red
in the masa?
-Guajillo pepper sauce.
-The masa is hot.
It's almost cooked.
-Halfway.
Is that how it's made
where you're from in Mexico?
-That's the way we do it.
-You do it hot.
Yeah.
I'm telling you, I learn
something new every day.
I had to come to Minnesota
to learn about
cooking masa halfway.
Wet a corn husk
with salty water,
then masa,
some of the pork.
-That's a big tamale, boss.
-It is, yeah.
How many of these
do you make a week?
-Maybe, like, 1,000.
-How many people work here?
How long are they
gonna steam?
One hour.
Okay.
Look at that.
This isn't my birthday.
All right. I'll try
to eat all of them.
And do we serve anything on it
or just as you see?
No, just like that.
That's probably
one of the most,
if not the most,
flavorful tamale I've ever had.
I'm savoring every bite.
Most of the time,
the masa has no flavor.
You're waiting to get
to the center of the tamale
to get the meat,
to get the filling.
Yeah, we give the flavor
to the masa and also the meat.
I'm converted.
If there was a county
in Flavortown named tamale,
that would be it, man.
That is it.
WOMAN: They're moist,
very flavorful.
They have the best tamales
in the Twin Cities.
The tamales have a very good
consistency,
especially the masa.
This is where
the "Triple D" crew eats
when they're not shooting
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
This is how often
we come here.
We've all filled out these cards
probably three or four times.
We have our punch cards.
What do you think
makes it so great?
We've been to so many
restaurants with you that,
when you find the real deal,
you recognize it.
Authentic Mexican food that
you don't need a passport for.
This is a great place.
It's cheap and fast,
and it's just great food.
-This is just perfect.
-You love what you do.
I do, yeah.
We have a lot of passion
for what we do, yeah.
Good dude. You got to come down
and meet these cats.
We've had
a lot of funky joints,
but this right here
[whistles] up top.
FIERI: Coming up, a tucked-away
spot in Los Angeles...
Oh, my gosh.
...with dishes so legit...
Off the hook.
...it's like being
right there in the Yucatan.
You learn something
new every day, baby.
♪♪
I'm here in Los Angeles,
just a few blocks from USC,
to check out a funky
little joint
that's housed here
in the Mercado La Paloma.
It's an economic
development building.
Now, they've got
a family in here
from the Yucatan
that is serving up legit,
real-deal Mexican food
that you probably
haven't seen before.
This is Chichén Itzá.
CETINA JR.: Order up,
cochinita pibil, table four.
Chichén Itzá's food is amazing.
-For you, sir.
-Out of control, man.
-Outrageous.
-Full-on flavor explosion.
We've got an order up
for table six.
They have taken the Yucatan
and brought the food,
the spices, the taste,
the texture here.
FIERI: That's exactly
the tradition
Chef Gilberto Cetina Jr.
wanted to preserve.
This is the food
that I grew up with.
This is what my grandma
used to cook.
This is what my mom used
to cook growing up in Yucatan.
I love it, man.
And so do his customers
ever since his dad
opened the joint in 2001.
This is very
labor-intensive food.
You can taste it.
-Longaniza asada.
So the longaniza is like
a chorizo sausage link.
It's full of flavor.
What are we gonna make?
-The longaniza asada.
-Longaniza asada.
Very traditional
Yucatan style.
We're gonna start
with pork shoulder,
ground fat and ground beef.
-Next?
Oregano,
garlic powder, clove...
onion, and we're gonna add
some vinegar.
Salt and...
-Cumin.
-Got it.
Mix this all by hand.
And then we're gonna
add the achiote paste.
Oh, oh, oh, hey.
Not going light with that, huh?
-About 4 ounces.
This is what gives
the great color
to a lot of Latin food.
All right.
So the casing goes on.
Natural sheep casing.
Anchor down.
-Oh, nice and thin.
Yep.
♪ Oh-ee-oh, oh-oh ♪
Perfect. Now we're going
to link 'em.
Now, how are we
gonna smoke them?
We're gonna hang them
on a stainless-steel dowel...
-Okay.
-...over embers.
They're gonna
sit there overnight.
Little bit of heat,
little bit of smoke.
Then we're
gonna grill these,
so here's the sausage after
being smoked and grilled,
serve it with some tortillas,
fire-roasted onions
and then
fire-roasted salsa.
So everything on here
was cooked on that same grill.
There is nothing about
that I don't love.
♪♪
It's a Yucatan hot dog.
Little bit of salt,
touch of spice,
great meat-to-fat ratio,
definitely get the wood
and the smoke.
That's fantastic.
-Thank you.
Longaniza asada.
This is excellent.
Just intense flavor,
something different
like I've never had before.
-Panuchos.
Super authentic,
really authentic.
-We're half-Hispanic.
-Yeah.
So this tastes
just like my grandma makes.
I love it.
This is also
a great community space.
There's other small,
locally owned businesses.
FIERI: All centered around a
main eating and hang-out space.
MAN: I come here to be able
to spend my dollar
with really awesome
mom-and-pop shops,
a lot of really
indigenous recipes.
So what's the next dish?
-Panucho.
-Panuchos.
It's one of my favorites,
and I always order them.
It's kind of like a tostada,
but it's infused
with black-bean paste.
And it's delicious.
All right. What are we doing
with this turkey?
We're gonna boil the legs,
and we're gonna
sous-vide the breasts.
Because that's what
you see every day
at a little kiosk Yucatan joint,
here in Los Angeles.
To cook the legs
in a stock pot,
we put water, salt,
garlic, oregano.
Okay.
Bay leaf,
black pepper, cilantro,
wings, legs and thighs.
-Like a little court bouillon.
-Exactly.
Now we're gonna prepare
the turkey breast...
-Okay.
-...for its sous-vide cooking.
Let's get into this.
Kosher salt, both sides.
Take a sous-vide bag,
a little bit
of cilantro in there.
And this is it
for the seasoning?
-That's it.
-We're gonna vacuum this?
-We are.
-Okay.
-150 degrees.
-Yeah.
-How long?
-Two and a half hours.
Got it.
This is not boiling.
This is simmering,
but it's precise,
and the beauty
about sous-vide
is you can go for long
periods of time,
and we're talking days,
to where it's so tender that,
when you open it out of the bag,
it'll just fall apart.
Okay.
-So we're gonna make
the tortillas now
for the panuchos.
Tortillas!
So we're going
to make little balls of masa.
In it goes.
♪♪
So why is this
going to puff up open?
Mine don't often puff up.
Once both layers
are cooked evenly,
you press down the tortilla,
and generally,
the steam in it puffs up,
and there it is.
You learn something
new every day, baby.
Okay.
-Open it up.
Some black beans ready.
-Okay.
Cover the whole,
and spread it out.
-Love it.
-Now we're gonna fry them.
Double-cooked tortilla.
-All right. Here we are, Chef.
-All right.
So we're gonna
make the achiote,
marinate it
to paint our turkeys...
-Paint our turkeys.
-...and put them on the grill.
-All right.
So we're gonna start
with some achiote paste
and then
fresh sour oranges.
-I love it.
-Some salt.
Now we're gonna
paint the turkey.
Some beautiful color
going in here,
and they're gonna
go on the grill.
Yeah.
Then, we're gonna shred
the meat off of the turkey.
-Right.
-Which part is the panucho?
-This is the panucho.
-That's the panucho.
This is
the traditional panucho.
This is what you would
get if you go eat
at a market
or mercado in Yucatan.
Little bit of lettuce,
some of the shredded leg
and sous-vide breast,
some pickled red onions,
tomato and
a slice of avocado.
-And that's all she wrote.
-That is the panucho.
♪♪
Man.
It's so tender,
delicious.
♪♪
Really simple
but done correctly.
I've had a lot of tacos.
I really appreciate
Mexican food.
It's subtle.
It's authentic.
That's a nostalgic dish.
Oh, my gosh.
Panuchos.
This is a very delightful
and complex dish.
What is your favorite thing
about those tacos?
Well, I really like
how it's crunchy,
but the avocado gives it
a wet texture
at the same time.
♪♪
Order up, table four.
WOMAN: I know I will
never be disappointed.
I love their food.
Authentic, baby.
Real deal.
-Thank you.
Off the hook!
FIERI: Up next, things are
on fire in Phoenix...
Those are hot.
-These are really hot.
FIERI: ...where five sisters
are rocking the tacos.
That's up there with some
of the best I've ever had.
And in Santa Barbara...
-See the halo?
-Yeah.
FIERI: ...a joint putting out
an A-plus posole.
Passed the test? You wrote
the curriculum, my friend.
Look at that.
I'm here in Phoenix, Arizona,
about 4 hours
north of the Mexican border.
Now, ask anybody
who goes down to Mexico a bunch
what kind of food
they really like down there,
and they're probably gonna
say, "Those little tacos
that you buy on the street."
So in the '80s,
the Ochoa family started selling
those little tacos
out of a taco truck.
Well, fast forward
20 years later,
and the five daughters are still
selling those great tacos here,
at Los Taquitos.
They're little street tacos.
One taco, you try it,
and that's how
you're hooked.
Excellent,
best tacos in town.
FIERI: Because they're still
made mom's way...
-You're the mom.
-I learned from my mother.
FIERI:
...by head chef Vickie Ochoa...
Fish tacos,
they're ready.
...and the rest of the family.
Fives sisters
all working together.
-Yeah.
-Do you get along?
-Not all the time.
-And there's a brother.
There's a brother in there.
-Are those almost done, bro?
-Almost.
FIERI: And together,
they're cranking out
more than 3,000 tacos a week...
Pick it up.
...and the rest
of the family cookbook.
-Flautas are cooked just right.
-The menudo, it's got some zip.
Garlic shrimp.
Chili relleno,
it's just excellent.
FIERI: But it's those
little tacos...
Big hands on
a little taco here.
...that started it all.
The fresh ingredients,
you can taste the meat.
Carne asada, chicken.
FIERI: Or a spiced,
pulled pork called...
-Carnitas.
-We're making our carnitas.
So that's a pork shoulder,
Boston butt.
Trim a little bit
of the fat off the top.
-Not a lot.
-Little bit of fat is flavor.
Yes. I think that's enough.
We leave our bone,
just give it a little slice,
and we're good to go.
We're gonna add
our two cinnamon sticks,
garlic, salt.
-Do it to taste.
-Our condensed milk.
Some condensed milk,
really?
-Mm-hmm.
-I've never seen it.
-Cola.
-Some soda.
Water.
Put them in our stove
and cover it.
Two hours until it
just falls apart.
After we take them out,
we shred them.
How is the flavor so great,
and there's no oil?
The condensed milk.
-And the soda.
-Okay. Let's make a taco.
VICKIE:
Here's our pork over here.
-Killer.
-Get our tortillas.
You have to spank them,
make sure they're well done.
-Bad little tortilla.
-Carnitas.
-A little cilantro.
-And red onion.
And then our salsa.
There you go.
-Mm.
-Good?
-No, they're not good.
-They're awesome?
I have some favorite
foods in my life,
and tacos
are one of them.
That's up there with some
of the best I've ever had.
The salsa, the onions,
the cilantro.
You have to have it
exactly like that.
That's the taste
of a taco.
Wow, that's good.
I absolutely love it.
It reminds me of home,
more traditional.
-It's so delicious.
-It's all home-made food.
FIERI:
And home-made salsas.
Large pico de gallo
to go.
-I love the green sauce.
-That's the red sauce.
FIERI: Made with roasted
red chilis...
Whoa.
...and an even hotter one
called bombero.
Bombero is fireman
in Spanish.
-It's hot.
-What are you enjoying?
-A bombero burrito.
-Say that five times fast.
Bombero burrito. Bombero
burrito. Bombero burrito.
-What are we gonna make first?
-The bombero sauce.
We're gonna start
with our tomato.
FIERI: Okay.
Red onion, water,
roast chilis.
-Those are hot.
-These are really hot.
-That's it?
-That's it.
And let it boil.
They sit there and steep
for about an hour,
let it cool down,
and now we're going
to make it into the salsa.
-Salsa.
Yep. We're gonna put
the whole mixture
to the blender,
and then we add some...
Little chipotle
with andobo sauce.
Uh-huh.
Black pepper, cumino.
-Or cumin.
-Mm-hmm.
A bit of garlic salt,
clove of garlic,
ketchup.
It has that sweet
and spicy flavor.
No, I got you.
You're gonna throw
the throttle on that, aren't ya?
Wah!
VICKIE:
Dump it in our pot.
And how long does
that cook down for?
45 minutes to an hour.
While that's going on, are
we gonna cook the chicken?
We're gonna work
on our grilled chicken.
-Okay.
-Cut it into fajitas style.
-You're like a surgeon.
-Learned since I was 14.
Then, what are we
gonna put on it?
-Some of our seasoning salt.
-A little cumin.
Garlic powder,
and then we'll add some vinegar.
Just mix it up.
And then, we'll put it
on our grill,
grill it until it
gets that crispy brown,
at least 10 minutes.
It's really spicy.
-Bombero man.
You're gonna need
the fireman.
-I am?
-Very spicy.
We'll get our tortilla
and put it on our grill.
Got our tortilla,
chicken ready, pico de gallo,
put rice on here,
wrap it up.
-And where does the sauce go?
-I'll get to that part.
-Don't rush it, huh?
-Yeah.
Walk him to our sauce.
My mouth is watering.
Bombero sauce,
some cheese,
and, Guy,
you're good to go.
Bombero burrito.
Careful.
It's hot.
Wow. There's a little bit
of kick to that.
The chicken has got
a little crunch
and a little crust on it,
but the sauce
with the ketchup,
little cool pico de gallo,
you get a little bit of...
A little bit
of the freshness.
Excellent.
It's a hot, spicy taste.
It's very good.
Very savory. It's got, like,
a nice, salty punch.
-Down-home cooking.
-I had a mission in life
to find the best taco
in the world.
I've found it.
-What's your busiest day?
-Every day.
That's a good week.
FIERI: So in our search
for south of the border,
there's definitely one city
I don't want to miss.
So here I am in Santa Barbara,
California.
Now, there's a few things
you can count on
for sure when you get here.
That's great weather,
avocado trees galore
and great Mexican food.
The only question is,
how do you tell the difference
between all the Mexican
restaurants?
For me, it's all about
quality and authenticity,
and from what I hear,
the joint to check out
is this place,
Lito's Mexican Food.
♪♪
Okay, guys. We need
a con platter relleno.
Carnitas dinner is ready.
It's the greatest Mexican food,
I'm telling you,
in, like, the world.
Real Mexican food,
like going to Mexico.
This is, like,
a family operation.
Your dad started this?
Pop said, "We're gonna open
up a place on Haley Street,"
and I said,
"Okay. Let's go."
FIERI:
That was more than 30 years ago,
and now second generation
Ernie Jimenez...
-Echilada dinner le pollo.
-...runs the joint.
So you've seen
a lot of changes,
but you guys have
stayed the same.
Lot of changes.
Yeah.
We have to stay the same,
got to be consistent.
Got to be consistent,
got to have quality,
and you got
to be authentic.
Home cooking. It's like going
to mom's house.
FIERI: But even mom ain't
rocking the traditional
pork stew, posole,
like these guys.
You can usually get it
on Friday, Saturday and Sunday.
But here, you can get it
every day if you want.
See?
See the halo?
-Yeah. See?
-Oh, it's the light.
Here we go
to posole land.
You're gonna love this.
And we have our
cubed-up pork meat here.
So this is the tri-tip
of the pig.
Right.
So we're just gonna cook
this down with some water.
We got our onions,
dry oregano,
cumin and our garlic
and blend it together.
We'll stew it for about an hour
or so, 45 minutes.
Until the pork is all cooked,
nice little simmer.
Now what?
-We add our hominy.
Okay. You see that corn?
Mmm.
Guajillo chili
that we blended already.
is not really spicy.
It's got a little bit
of a bite to it,
really rich in flavor,
one of my favorites.
Okay. So now,
we cook this down.
How much longer
is this gonna go?
About another half an hour.
We're ready to go.
You're gonna love this.
♪♪
Serve it up, boss.
Let's do this.
All right.
I feel like
I'm an expectant father.
And then the nice
little platter
with some cabbage
and some radish.
Radishes.
I do cilantro, onions,
bunch of the cabbage.
Mmm. There is nothing
that is as satisfying
in the soup world
as posole.
Big, tender,
juicy pieces of pork.
You get a little bit
of the crunch
because the cabbage
can survive,
and that guajillo pepper
in the broth, mmm.
There's the hominy
right there,
soaked up all
that awesome flavor.
That's mom.
Awesome.
-Passed the test.
-Passed the test?
You wrote the curriculum,
my friend.
Look at that, mmm.
-Thanks.
In the lifetime
that you've had posole,
how does that rate?
-Number one.
Every weekend,
got to have it.
Lito's is the staple.
Everybody knows everybody.
It's a great place.
I love it, man.
Nice place.
Nice to see that the family
is still running it.
-It's the only way to go.
-You got it.
FIERI: Coming up on this
full hour of major Mexican...
This is gnarly.
...killer tostadas
and tortas...
You can't make this
sandwich fast enough.
...cooked up in something
you're just not
seeing every day.
That's one of the biggest
taco trucks I've ever seen.
♪♪
You know, there's just
something about "Triple D"
and finding great food
in unexpected places,
like vehicles.
So here we are in Tampa,
Florida,
to check out some righteous
Mexican food in a school bus.
This is Taco Bus.
Welcome to Taco Bus.
What can I get you?
MAN: The bus is fun.
You feel like
you're in this
little corner of Mexico.
-Two chicharron taco.
-Very authentic Mexican food.
-The tacos are awesome.
-Two tacos coming up.
Chicken burrito, I have a little
bit of an addiction for it.
-The steak tostada.
-This is my favorite food.
That's one of the biggest
taco trucks I've ever seen.
How big is that school bus?
-It's about 35 feet.
FIERI: But when Rene Valenzuela
opened this joint in '91...
First,
we looked at cargo vans,
some little vans,
some little trailers.
We needed
a bigger kitchen.
Order up.
FIERI: So they got a bus.
Carne asada burrito
coming up.
And since '99,
Rene is using it
to crank out the classics
he grew up cooking in Mexico...
Fish tacos.
We wanted to do food
that's very authentic,
very deep in Mexico.
...from fried pork rinds
with salsa verde...
It's spicy.
It's really good.
FIERI: ...to the Mayan standard
cochinita pibil...
The meat is just tender
and just goes down like water.
FIERI: ...and this regional
specialty with pulled pork
and ancho pepper sauce.
-Chilorio torta.
-Never seen it.
I've been eating
Mexican food all my life.
To make chilorio, first,
we're gonna make carnitas.
We got a Boston butt
right here.
We're gonna take
the fat out.
FIERI: Okay. So cut it
into small pieces.
Right.
Put a little bit of salt.
And now we're gonna put it
into the hot pork lard.
-It builds a little crust.
-Right.
Put some Mexican
bay leaves.
Allspice, interesting,
I like that.
And orange.
Here you go.
-Everybody in the pool.
-Simmer, so it's frying slowly.
-How many hours?
-About a couple hours.
All right.
So it's all cooled down now.
We shred it?
-That's right.
Mmm. I like that spice
with the allspice in there.
We'll shred it,
make the salsa,
then make the torta.
-That's right.
-Got it.
-Anchos.
-Love anchos.
-Oh, yeah.
Oh.
And pasillas.
Pasillas.
We got a hot griddle.
We're gonna
put them in there.
It's gonna help
awaken the flavors.
And then we're gonna
steep them in hot water?
-Right.
-Okay. So we keep the lid on it,
so it keeps
the peppers submerged.
Nice. So what are you
doing with the seeds?
We're just opening them up here?
-Right.
You can't make the sauce
with the seeds
and then strain the seeds out.
They become too bitter.
-That's right.
-We take all these.
Now we're gonna
grind these up.
-Yes, for the chilorio sauce.
-I know this routine.
Put in the red peppers
in the blender.
I'm gonna put
a little bit of the water.
-Okay.
-I take some oregano.
It's different.
-One of my favorite.
Vinegar.
And then
garlic cloves and salt.
After we put it
through the blender,
we're gonna strain it.
♪♪
Then we're gonna
put the sauce.
We're gonna fry it.
With a little bit of the lard
that we put the pork in.
-That's right.
-This is gnarly.
That's what you got
to do right there.
You got to cook off
a little bit of that bitterness.
We put the carnitas,
already shredded.
And we're just gonna
sit there and cook this up,
let it coat.
-Right.
And then we're going
to make the torta.
That's right.
You can't make
this sandwich fast enough.
So this
is homemade bread.
Yeah. Refried beans
on the bottom.
So now we put
the chilorio on top.
Refried beans almost work
like the mayonnaise.
-That's right.
-Okay, a little queso.
Little queso on top,
jalapeños,
then tomatoes,
white onions,
marinated onions.
-Cabbage.
Don't be stingy
with the cabbage.
Okay.
And cilantro.
Here you go.
-Look at that.
Mmm.
That is out of bounds, dude.
All right.
The freshness of the bread,
right off the bat.
Then, you get this hot,
little bit spicy of the meat.
Then, you get
the crunch of the onion.
And a little snap
from the jalapeño. Mmm.
This has got to be one of
the best tortas I've ever had.
-All right.
-I mean, one of the best, dude.
That sandwich rocks.
I like Mexican pork,
and this is the porkiest pork.
MAN: The tenderness of the meat
and the crunchiness
of the vegetables in there,
just like you're in Mexico.
Two tacos chicharron
y speciale, rice and beans.
MAN #2: The Taco Bus, there's
really nothing else like it.
This one was here
before food trucks were cool.
The nice thing is
we don't move it around.
People can find it.
FIERI:
Anytime, day or night.
If you come here at 4:00 a.m.,
you're hungry.
They're all part
of Taco Bus Nation.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
How late are they open?
They're open 24/7.
-No.
-Yeah.
For me, it's the healthy food
was what sold me.
FIERI: Because they're serving
up Mexican classics
with a little vegetarian spin.
VALENZUELA:
Grilled tofu tacos.
I'm having the veggie burrito
right now, and it's amazing.
My new favorite is
the butternut squash tostada.
FIERI: Yeah. He's putting
butternut squash on a tostada.
VALENZUELA: It's still Mexican.
It's not well known,
and that's something unique
that brings you to Mexico.
-This is delicious.
-The squash.
You wait until you try it.
It's famous here.
Okay.
First, start
with butternut squash, fresh.
Just gonna cut it
into large pieces.
-And where is this recipe from?
-Yucatan.
So that's it, boil it with
the seeds and everything in it?
-Right.
-Down in the water?
-That's right.
-How long?
Once it boils, about two
or three minutes.
It's got to be tender
but not too much
because, otherwise,
it gets all mushy.
Don't want to get it mushy.
All right.
So now it's boiled
and cooled a little bit.
Now we're gonna
take the seeds out?
Right. We also got
to take the skin out.
-We're gonna chop it up?
-Right.
And what's the next step?
We're gonna put
a little bit of oil, onions.
-Red bell pepper.
-Tomatoes, habanero peppers.
[ Whistles ]
I'm gonna put just
a little bit before
I add the butternut squash.
-Squash.
-Now, the butternut squash
is gonna get
a little softer here.
We're gonna
just cook it down
so it's a little bit
more tender?
That's right.
-We ready?
-We're ready.
So we're gonna top
our tostada with it.
Looks like he's putting
a fruit cocktail on there.
Now put tomatoes, onions,
cilantro and cheese.
There you go.
-That's a lot.
You can do it.
There you go.
It's got good texture.
Tostada is nice and crunchy,
and the squash is
not fall-apart soft.
The mixture of the red bell
pepper and the onions
and that little bit
of the habanero
was really done
the right way.
I'd order it again
in a heartbeat.
-All right.
-It's really nice.
-Thank you.
-Butternut squash tostada.
It's crispy, very light.
Great flavor you can't find
in a lot of places.
Cochinita pibil.
It's the best Mexican food
in West Florida.
Two steak tacos.
Anybody that's into this kind of
food knows about Taco Bus?
-Yeah.
-Oh, absolutely.
-Can I get a torta chilorio?
-I can go home now, dude.
We'll wrap up the torta
for lunch later, for lunching.
Do me a favor
and wrap up the bus
and take it to my casa.
-All right.
-The bomb.
FIERI: Up next,
seafood in Salt Lake...
I got nothing
but happy on that.
...and enjoy making some
big bad burritos...
Awesome.
...then, green chili
as real as it gets...
I've had
a lot of chili verde.
This is fantastic.
...right in the middle
of Missouri.
-I think it's a good thing.
-I think it's a great thing.
Usually, on "Triple D,"
you see me cruising
the convertible '67,
but when I find a joint
that's got a car this sick,
well, I just got to stop
and check it out.
And it's not just the car
that's unique here
at the Lone Star Taqueria
in Salt Lake City.
They're doing Mexican food
the real-deal way.
Another chicken puerre,
no cilantro.
-It's delicious.
-Salsa, everybody is fine?
-Orders up, please.
-Casual and funky.
The car and the boots
really stuck out.
There's no other place like it.
Lone quesadillas, solamente.
-Is it always this chaotic?
-Yeah.
I feel like
I walked into a fiesta.
-Two tacos.
-The food is fabulous.
-Pretty much awesomeness.
-Enjoy the fish taco?
Yes. It's money.
Everybody is happy?
FIERI: Because this ain't
Susan Harry's first rodeo.
It's all I've done
since I was the age of 13.
Taco de pescado.
FIERI: After running all kinds
of restaurants,
she wanted to open
a Mexican place.
-Carne adovada.
-Right here.
FIERI:
So she brought in an old friend,
Manuel Valdez...
-Shellfish taco up.
-...and his brother...
-Chicken burrito.
FIERI: ...to do the food
they grew up with.
-Appreciate it. Have a good day.
-I mean, it's like family.
-It's awesome.
-Where I came for tacos.
Big, big burritos.
FIERI: And some of the biggest
favorites here...
Fish taco combo up.
-...are seafood...
-Nothing better.
FIERI: ...in Utah.
Is it easy
to get fresh seafood here?
-Oh, yes. It is.
-Really?
-Every day.
-Queso pescada ahita.
Fresh ahi.
-I'm having a salmon taco.
Sometimes, it's cod.
Sometimes, it's sole.
-Sea bass.
-It's kind of like roulette.
You don't know what you're
gonna get that day.
I got the shark taco.
-Mahi mahi, red snapper.
-Okay.
I'm running out of fingers.
-They have everything.
-Camarones.
Shrimp burrito.
FIERI: This one is
on the menu every day.
I have to have these
at least regularly.
You make separate vegetables
for the shrimp taco
and the shrimp burritos.
VALDEZ: We use bell peppers
and red onions.
-Julienne?
-Julienne. Perfect.
They're not to be beautiful.
They're just to get done.
Yes.
Exactamente.
So now, what we're gonna do
is we're gonna add
all the ingredients.
Mm-hmm.
Garlic, cayenne, black pepper.
We're gonna put it all in?
California chili.
Little salt.
New Mexico chili.
And then a little bit
of the soybean oil.
-Soybean oil?
-Soybean.
Wow. How Rive Gauche of you.
-Mm-hmm.
So sauté that up.
Takes what, 2 hours?
Maybe less but,
you know, around there.
Wow. Look how much
that cooked down.
♪♪
Wow.
That's great flavor.
[ Whistles ] Little bit
of heat on that.
Little bit of oil,
whole-tail shrimp.
Just gonna throw
a little bit of garlic in there.
Now, we go fast
with these, right?
Yep. Now, we have
our peppers.
We've got juice
already in there, too.
Warm up our tortilla.
That's a big tortilla
right there.
-Look at that.
-We've got our rice.
We've got some
of our beans.
FIERI: In those frijoles,
we got manteca in that,
or what do we got?
No, vegetable oil, cumin,
garlic and salt.
-Okay.
-And you're done.
Just a little bit of cheese.
-Now the camarones.
-Just put a little.
-Don't forget that guy.
-Oh, that guy right there.
Cilantro. We got
a little bit of onions,
the fresh onions,
tomatoes.
Little bit of lettuce.
-Looks good.
Little bit
of sour cream here.
No, no, no, no.
Go all the way over.
That way, you bring this back.
-Then you bring that one back.
-And then roll over.
-It's like the taquito method.
That's what
I'm talking about.
I have to be
able to see it.
Mmm.
What's that called,
Killer Burrito?
Really good.
You definitely get the distinct
flavor of the peppers.
I got nothing
but happy on that.
Seriously, awesome.
Awesome!
Nice and spicy,
lots of interesting peppers.
-It's got a kick to it.
-I love it.
Burritos good?
You eat the food,
and you're hooked.
Taco asada combo.
Normally, in Mexico,
I'd be eating this on a street.
You just have to
keep coming back.
Best taco joint in Utah,
for sure.
Is that your car?
No.
The Camaro and the station
wagon, even swap?
Oh, absolutely not.
Okay.
I'll give you 500 bucks.
FIERI:
Now we're headed directly east
for some more good food
and a great story.
You got to dig
restaurant romances.
You know, boy meets girl,
but he's from a foreign country.
They hit it off, well,
then they get married.
They move back to her hometown,
and they open a restaurant.
I mean, it's, like,
made for a TV movie
except, here, it's real.
I'm in Chesterfield,
about 30 miles west of downtown
St. Louis, Missouri,
to check out this joint,
Espino's Mexican Bar and Grill.
Pick up the carnitas, guys.
Let's go.
The flavors are powerful.
The food here is incredible.
Mr. Espino,
he is the best chef.
FIERI:
That's Mr. Artemio Espino,
originally
from Michoacán, Mexico.
Here's enchiladas, guys.
Pick up.
FIERI: In '04, he opened
the joint with his wife,
Roseanne...
-Hi, Carrie. How are you?
FIERI: ...you know, the hometown
girl I was talking about,
and the hometown,
straight-up barbecue country.
Their ribs are to die for.
FIERI:
So are the family recipes,
like a mole passed down
through the generations
and a pork chili verde
that is off the hook.
The pork chili verde.
Pick up.
FIERI: What are we
gonna make first?
The green salsa
for the pork chili verde.
First, we're going
to get garlic.
-The serranos?
-Jalapeños and serranos.
Now
you got your onions,
and then you put
your tomatillos.
You hear them sizzling?
See?
Now we put the water.
And we're gonna let it go
for at least a half hour.
And while that cooks,
in this container right here...
-Okay.
-...we're gonna add onions.
-Cilantro.
-Cilantro, salt, white pepper.
Okay. So when that's cooked,
we drop it in here?
Yeah.
Then, we mix it.
Now we're gonna do
the pork.
Olive oil,
the chopped garlic.
Turn it fast,
or you'll burn the garlic.
The whole pan,
you got your pork.
So you brown the meat.
-Black pepper.
-Oregano.
Dry oregano,
your lemon pepper.
I've never seen lemon
pepper in Mexico.
That one is a new thing
up here, I guess.
Now, you add your cumino.
-Cumin.
Put your salt on it.
Now, you add your onions
to give more body to the sauce.
Diced green chilis.
Then, I got pork base...
-Okay.
...to add more flavor
to it.
I like the bottom-
of-the-spoon move.
Okay. And then, we're
gonna put this sauce.
This is the sauce,
the one I make.
See? Right to the end,
you put your cilantro.
Stir it.
Cover it
and lower the heat.
In one hour, you have
the pork chili verde.
There you are.
-Nice.
Nice and tender,
ready to eat.
♪♪
This is one of my favorite
Mexican dishes.
♪♪
Killer.
Perfect amount of spice.
Look at that.
You just push on the pork,
and it just falls apart,
a little jalapeño,
a little garlic,
the acidity
of the tomatillos.
But I got to tell you, Chef,
it is delicious.
I've had a lot
of chili verde.
This is fantastic.
-Thanks.
We have the puerco
con chili verde.
It's a little sweet,
a little tangy.
It's unbelievably tender.
For a guy that came from Mexico
on his 18th birthday
to look what you've
done for yourself,
making this kind of food
and offering it
to these folks here
in Chesterfield, what a life.
-I think it's a good thing.
-I think it's a great thing.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, it's Mexican
madness in Omaha...
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
...from classic enchiladas
and chimichangas...
Bye-bye, let's fry.
...to puff the magic tortilla.
Mm, that's killer!
This one is
a great family story.
Here I am in Omaha, Nebraska.
In 1914, a Belgian immigrant
put up this building
and opened up a pharmacy.
He later passed it on
to his son.
Well, decades later,
his son retires,
and it looks like
the Bogard family legacy
is gonna end on this corner.
Well, that is until
the grandson stepped up
and said,
"I'll take a shot,"
moved back from Miami
and reopened the place
his way as a taqueria...
Two beef hard shells.
...serving all the classics.
Chicken chimichanga,
it's great.
-Beef enchilada.
-Great food.
-FIERI: But the heavy hitter...
-One more beef.
...is something
Brad Bogard calls
the California taco...
-Here we go.
FIERI: ...even though he
discovered it
on a trip to the Caribbean...
It's that
puffy-shell taco.
...that he brought to Omaha...
No lettuce.
...when he decided
to settle down
and open this joint
in the old family building.
Beef taco coming up.
Just one hitch.
Never worked at a restaurant
before in my life.
Never worked at one.
Went down to the Mexican
grocery store, "Pollo?
Chicken?"
-They started giving you ideas.
Yeah, and they, like,
pointed at what to use.
Oh, there's
the tortilla recipe.
And that's how you
started making tortillas.
-Yeah.
-Give me the rundown.
You start with wheat flour,
then sea salt, baking soda.
So that's gonna give it
some of the leavening.
Vegetable shortening.
Then some hot water.
Crank this baby up.
So once the dough works,
do you knead it?
You got
to knead that dough.
Now, who taught you
how to do this?
-Nobody.
-Really?
Throw my dough down,
then we put it
in the bun divider.
Look at that.
What is that, circa 1840?
-Patent 1931.
-Wow.
Into the slot,
confinement ring.
Because you will
stay in there.
Pull it down,
then we hit the button.
Nice drop down.
Activate.
-Really?
-Pull it up.
Wow. Look at those
little biscuits of friendship.
Now, you go ahead
and roll these out by hand.
Exactly.
Power it up.
And we don't do it
until we get your order.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
You can make them ahead of time
and just wax paper them.
Could. Don't.
I want their tacos
tasting like I want my tacos.
So that's it.
Now we can stuff it
with whatever we want.
Steak, chicken, beef.
Now, this is what we're going
to use to make the carne asada?
The steak, exactly.
You take it over to the slicer,
put the spices together,
a little black pepper,
sea salt,
onion salt,
cayenne pepper,
the oregano,
which I like.
I like the seasoning
mix on that.
And then, we grill it?
-Open flame.
FIERI: Medium rare on both
sides, so it doesn't dry out.
You got it. And after it cools,
then, we slice it.
If you slice it right away...
-It'll lose all the juice.
Exactly.
That's some
pretty good carne.
These get popped
inside of here.
Right.
That's a healthy
little portion.
And that's it.
Bye-bye, let's fry.
-Let's do it.
-After it's done cooking,
you let it drain a little bit
of the oil.
About 3 minutes. Should
we see what she looks like?
That takes a little something.
-Look at that.
Lettuce.
We shred our own cheese.
Queso. Look at that.
That's outstanding.
Mmm. The meat has got
great flavor, crunchy.
Look at all
the juice in there.
Mmm, that's killer.
Do I look like I just
took a bath in that or what?
Wow, that's good.
Nice job, man.
-Appreciate that.
-Good texture.
It's got a great taste to it.
-Tasted homemade.
My mom didn't
make them this good.
That's kind of like
the seal of approval.
We got to make
that tu-tung sound.
Tu-tung.
It's quick. It's easy,
and it's great food.
It tastes really fresh.
I want everything
cooked that day.
This salsa is great.
FIERI: Two kinds -- the red...
Tastes like somebody
just chopped up a tomato
and put it in a bottle.
FIERI: ...and the green,
made with fresh jalapeños.
Look at that.
-That's good.
That's money.
-That's money.
All the way down.
FIERI: And Brad keeps serving up
all the favorites.
-Three hard-shell tacos.
-There we go. Burrito.
The nachos supreme, really good.
FIERI: And when he heads
back to the fryer...
-Chicken chimi.
-Let's make a chimichanga.
Big deep-fried burrito.
-Exactly.
-80-20 ground beef.
Add the seasonings right after
we get the meat in there.
-Ancho?
-Ancho chili pepper.
-The chipotle.
-Sea salt.
-Okay.
-And onion salt.
-Add a little water.
-Everybody is in the pool.
You're gonna let it sit here
and cook for, what, 2 hours?
-Right at it.
-So that's cooked down.
I mean, that is,
like, beef sauce.
[ Whistles ] And this is
the method, huh?
The spices help separate
that oil from the meat.
That's precise.
So let these cool down,
and then what goes down?
Pinto beans, we sort every one
by hand, looking for rocks.
The thing I love is that,
when you were hanging down
at the Mexican market,
you got some really
particular information,
something like, sorting beans,
which is quite an art,
very seldom done.
And then you cook the beans,
mix the beans
into the ground beef.
Just a few.
Flour tortilla.
Put a little steam
on it so it's pliable.
Exactly, make it pliable,
so you can fold it up.
-So it doesn't crack.
-A little refried beans,
good amount of meat,
onions.
You know
how I like cheese.
-Cheesy.
-Like that.
Are we gonna wedge
that in there again?
Then over to the fryer.
-You got it.
-There we go.
-Plate it really quick.
Lettuce on there.
Cheese. Couple olives.
So let's take a gander
at that bad boy.
Crispy outside.
Creamy, cheesy on the inside.
Mmm.
That's awesome, man.
You know my favorite part?
Little bit of onion
you put in there.
Well done, brother.
-Thanks, man.
Look at that.
MAN:
It's got homemade flavors
you don't find just
anywhere else.
All the meat and cheese,
it's just good.
FIERI: And Brad just
keeps on frying.
Chicken enchilada, it definitely
tastes fresh and homemade.
So we're gonna make
the shredded chicken.
Chicken down,
little sea salt in there.
Water, just enough
to cover it.
Simmer it for
an hour and a half,
let it break down.
It almost starts
to shred for you.
How much does that make for you
for a day?
-Half a day.
-Really?
And then,
you'll do it again.
Yeah. Just keep going.
Keep going.
So the chicken
gets shredded up.
We just want to add
a little pungent flavor.
This mixture of cumin,
cayenne and paprika.
Then you roll it around.
That's what
I'm talking about.
That's killer.
That's some really nice flavor.
We need the sauce
for the enchiladas.
Start with
the tomato sauce.
We've got the chili
powder, ancho.
Well, the ancho chili
farmers here in Nebraska are
doing really well
with all your use.
Then, we roll in...
-Chipotle.
Onion salt.
The sea salt.
A little garlic.
A little agua.
You let that warm up.
This is one of the things
about Mexican food
people don't know is
a lot of it is preparation.
It's the low and slow idea.
-Let that warm up.
We take some canola oil.
-Sauce is hot.
Dip, fry.
Fry. Out.
Put it in this
enchilada sauce.
Heat the tortilla
with that salsa in the oil.
It really makes
that enchilada sauce...
-Just soak right into it.
-...soak right into it.
And that tortilla
holds the sauce.
Dip.
Fry, out.
I like the concept.
Cook that right into it.
You look like
Edward Scissorhands with those.
-We're doing the enchiladas.
-Look at that chicken.
Little bit of cheese
inside also.
Then, it has to go
through the steamer.
I think we're ready.
-Nice.
Roll it up here.
Top it with some more cheese.
Okay.
Look at that.
Now, I always
dress it in lettuce,
couple of my homemade
flour tortilla chips.
Mmm.
Good, man. I got to
tell you something, dude.
That tortilla,
fantastic flavor, mm.
That is really good, man.
-Thank you.
The chicken is really juicy.
The melted cheese
makes it really good.
-The California Taco?
-It's fast, easy and unique.
-How we doing?
-Congratulations, man.
Got a great joint.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
Here, I got something
for you, man.
Seriously?
You carved this by hand?
All out of a watermelon?
-A watermelon, yeah.
-You're crazy.
You're like a surgeon.