Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
...we're catching some rays
and grabbing some grub...
Ding!
...all across America...
I'm just gonna hold on,
'cause this looks like
it's gonna be a rough ride.
...from a Hawaiian
shrimp truck...
You'll love this place.
...to an Outer Bank
seafood stop...
[ Deep voice ]
Enjoy the local fare.
...to a landmark
Florida fish house...
[ Normal voice ]
It's like a piece of history.
...plus sushi in Mexico...
Really?
...Pakistani in Arizona...
Ah, I can't stop.
...and in Cali...
Bring the kids down!
...classic 'cue
and one funky food truck.
Wow!
So grab some SPF,
relax, and dig in.
This is out of bounds.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
♪ Unh ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
in case you haven't noticed,
the food truck invasion
has happened.
I mean, we're seeing them
everywhere -- Texas,
Los Angeles,
Vancouver, you name it.
And now here
on the Island of Oahu
in the North Shore,
this is the Big Wave Shrimp
truck.
♪♪
You can't go wrong
eating at Big Wave Shrimp.
Yeah, absolutely perfect.
Everyone's favorite place
on Oahu to eat.
Which started when Mike Stacey
gave his wife, Kate,
something she's always wanted --
her own restaurant.
So it used to be
a handyman bus.
And you took it and converted
it into a restaurant?
Yes.
On wheels.
Spicy shrimp.
And started cranking out their
take on North Shore staples.
So local style
is Hawaiian style,
but you put your
Thai flair to it?
Correct.
So, what kind of food
do you make here?
The main thing is the shrimp.
So all kind of shrimp here
on the shrimp truck?
Lemon peppered shrimp.
I already know what you want --
Coconut Shrimp.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm having the crunchy shrimp.
I mean, I like it.
It's tasty.
We're gonna miss the batter.
For the crunchy shrimp?
Yes, sir.
Tempura.
Tempura batter.
Sugar.
Sugar!
So, that's a 21, 25 shrimp,
butterflied all
the way open, no shell.
Okay, so we dip them
in the batter.
Yes.
Into the panko.
Panko.
Let that kind of stick
on there.
Vegetable oil.
Now we are ready
to put in the pan.
Every time somebody orders
something, make it to scratch?
Yes, every time.
[ Whistles ]
And we cook fast.
After we finish,
we put on the plate.
10 pieces.
Sweet and sour,
or sweet chili?
Sweet chili.
Mmm.
There's something about
getting shrimp on the island
when they're not frozen,
so tender.
You can't beat it.
Crazy, but great!
-Crunchy shrimp!
-It's just insane, it's so good.
As soon as it hits your mouth,
it's just, like, mmm, melts.
I'm a junkie --
shrimp junkie.
But you make other things.
From shoyu chicken
and locally-grown sweet corn
to Kate's Korean-style
short ribs.
These are just, like,
perfect.
Barbecue short ribs
for you.
for me?
Yes.
I'm just gonna hold on,
'cause this looks like
it's gonna be a rough ride.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, I'm sorry.
I start to cut
the short ribs.
Then you season?
This is a chicken broth
seasoning.
Chicken base and a little bit
of garlic salt?
Correct.
This sits here with the dry rub
on it for how long?
It's about one or two hours.
And then we're gonna
cook it in the pan?
Mm-hmm.
A little oil.
This is a thin slice,
which is more of the Asian
or Korean style.
Just because of the bone
and the connective tissue,
it's almost sweet,
real great meat flavor.
And that's just it.
Nice and simple, huh?
Chicken base
and garlic salt.
♪ Chicken base
and garlic salt ♪
and garlic salt for me ♪
♪ I said it's chicken base
and garlic salt ♪
♪ Chicken base
and garlic salt for me ♪
[ Laughs ]
Next seasoning,
Hondashi.
An Asian seasoned salt.
And then one the rice,
furikake.
Furikake is a traditional
Hawaiian-Asian seasoned salt.
I love it!
Look at that,
nice and crispy.
Anything I can eat with
my hands, of course, I want to.
But short rib just by itself,
it's got great flavor.
Get a little bit of the rice
with the furikake.
Put a bite of that...
[Muffled] with this.
What's not to like
about this?
Barbecued short ribs!
They're really juicy,
and they're not overcooked.
WOMAN:
The ribs are really good.
There's a lot of different
flavor to it.
And everything that they make
is handmade, real deal.
Everything.
FIERI:
Make all these people happy,
you should be, like,
the Mayor or something.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you so much.
You'll love this place.
♪♪
FIERI: So now, we're headed
to sunny Cabo San Lucas.
I'm here to check out a joint
that my buddy Gorilla --
You remember Gorilla Rich from
Gorilla Barbecue in Pacifica?
He says he's been to this place
a bunch of times.
It's off the hook.
This is Tiki Bar.
♪♪
Fresh tacos ready.
This is our local spot
to come to.
It's in kind of
a touristy area.
Locals and tourists,
we mix and mingle well.
It's right here on the marina.
I love their food, everything.
FIERI: Just the kind of place
owner Moises Gonzales
was looking for after
he became a local in 2005.
A place where people could
come in, hang out --
I couldn't find a place
like home in Cali.
Really?
And to make it feel more
like home for the locals,
Chef Manuel Aradando
is taking advantage
of the surroundings.
I know it's fresh 'cause if I
didn't catch it, my friends did.
So, fresh fish all the time,
every day.
Every day.
Sushi's excellent here.
That's right --
sushi in a Mexican joint.
It's fresh.
You can't fake that.
FIERI: From the classic rolls
like the rainbow and spider
to the turducken of sushi...
Ebi Nagasaki.
...layers of fresh fish
inside a butterflied shrimp roll
drizzled with
homemade eel sauce.
You see it every day.
This that we're gonna prepare
today is the ebi Nagasaki.
So, what we're gonna do is
start with this surimi salad.
And this is imitation crab.
Imitation crab.
So, we're gonna add
a little bit of mayonnaise,
the masago, that is the...
Fish eggs.
...fish eggs.
And the togarashi...
Togarashi.
...the Japanese peppers
with a little bit
of sesame seeds and orange zest.
Orange zest, and last
but not least, sriracha.
So, then what we're gonna do is
just mix it up a little bit.
Want to try it?
I like where that starts.
I mean, I don't know why you've
got to do anything else to it.
It just tastes great.
We're gonna take
our Pacific blue shrimp.
We are gonna butterfly it.
Okay.
And then, we do one more.
So once and then twice.
That's correct.
Then we're gonna go ahead
and do our salad.
Okay.
Next, we're gonna do
a piece of salmon.
This guy's a surgeon!
There. So, we do...
There we go.
That this. Here we are.
Okay.
Then, we fold it
and we wrap it in the nori,
in the seaweed.
I'm picking up what
you're laying down.
These are beautiful.
Then we have tempura
and then bread crumbs.
Fold it in tempura like this,
and then the bread.
♪♪
All good to go.
Okay.
So, next thing,
we're gonna fry it.
♪♪
And we're gonna serve it
with eel sauce.
♪♪
A little rose, very nice.
Wasabi and mango sauce,
and then more eel sauce.
Finish it off with a little
bit of sesame seeds,
and we'll add some
microgreens.
Gorgeous plate.
Okay.
The way you treat the shrimp
and the tenderness
of that shrimp
is outrageous.
Outrageous.
Although it was fried,
it doesn't have
a real heavy
fried taste to it.
It's very light.
The salad has just
enough of the...
sriracha,
a little hint
of the salmon.
This is outstanding.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Ebi Nagasaki up.
Super crispy
and really delicious.
MAN: We're at the Southern tip
of the Baha Peninsula,
where the fishing is
the greatest in the world.
So it's the freshest
in town.
♪♪
I love this restaurant.
I come here every day,
ever since he's had it.
Just bring people here.
It's a wonderful spot.
I'm just like you guys.
You know, you go somewhere,
you're like,
"Where should I go eat?"
A funky little place, small,
and these guys
do it legit.
We gotta do more sushi
on "Triple D."
♪♪
FIERI: Up next, a killer
culinary cruiser...
A lot going on in there!
...bringing a taste
of Singapore
right into Orange County.
You're the bomb-dot-com.
♪♪
You been here before?
I hear it's the bomb.
It's a Singapore concept.
And they're never in the same
location for lunch or dinner.
They're from Orange County,
California.
This is Chomp Chomp Nation.
Yeah, it'll be me and the
millions of people with me.
♪♪
All day two steaks,
tofu, bean, and lamb.
Got some fun, unique food.
Singapore tofu burger,
please.
How do you describe to people
what Singaporean food is?
It's exotic,
tropical Chinese food.
FIERI: Brought to America
by the husband and wife team
of Robert Zuetell
and Gina Galvan.
We call it quick gourmet.
Quick gourmet.
It comes out in three minutes,
looks like a million dollars.
Not that you couldn't tell,
Robert's background
is in restaurant PR.
And Gina, I mean, she's just
traveled the world
as a food technologist.
I worked for all kinds
of restaurant chains
and food manufacturers.
To develop food concepts
and food recipes?
And she's picked up flavors
that are turning the truck
into a spice market
with an outrageous blend
mixed into this top seller.
Crab cake.
A delicious lunch
for a good price.
[ Beatboxing ]
[ Laughs ]
When I went to Singapore,
I figured out this is what
Singapore tastes like.
And that's why I call this,
the aromatics package.
So, the key ingredients --
ginger...
Ginger, lemongrass,
shallots, galangal.
Galangal, a relative
of the ginger.
Yes.
Garlic, Thai chilies,
and finally,
the kaffir lime leaf.
Now, the kaffir lime leaf,
there's just such an intensity
and such a richness...
and such an amazing,
aromatic flavor
and essence that comes
from it. Okay.
You're just gonna make
this into a paste?
Kind of a rough paste.
All right.
There it be.
[ Whistles ]
Awesome.
So, what are we
gonna make with this?
We're gonna make
crab cake sandwich.
Andale!
What is this?
This is rice cake.
Cook it in this plastic,
and it compresses
the rice as it cooks.
And in Singapore,
it's called ketupat.
It tastes like you
cooked a bunch of rice
a little overcooked,
and then compressed it.
Mm-hmm. The reason I put
this in the crab cake
is because it makes the crab
stand up nice and firm.
The aromatics packet.
Sri Lanken blue crab
leg and claw.
Chili crab sauce.
[ Smacks lips ]
I like that.
Sweet chili sauce,
mayonnaise, panko.
Panko bread crumbs.
Egg.
This is looking good.
What is that over there?
[ Laughs ]
Caught you!
Can you get me that, please,
which is the panko?
We're gonna make it
a little crispy on the outside.
That's a good-looking
crab cake.
Okay. Now, we're gonna
walk over to the fryer.
Everything's cooked in there.
So, you're just frying it
enough to put a crisp on it.
Yep.
What are we gonna make?
Our lemongrass
kaffir lime vinaigrette.
Grape-seed oil, rice vinegar,
our aromatics,
kaffir lime leaf,
whole thing.
Shallots,
country Dijon mustard.
In an emulsifier?
You're pretty smart, there.
Chinese white pepper,
lychee juice.
Lychee juice!
It's tropical and exotic.
Sweet chili sauce
and cilantro.
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
Yes!
Mmm.
Now we're making the slaw.
The slaw.
Green cabbage
and red cabbage.
Carrots, here we go.
Daikon.
Ooh, I like the daikon.
Cucumber, mango.
Oh, mango!
Red onion, green apple.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
And then, we'll serve the slaw
dressing on it to order?
Yes.
Now, we're gonna
plate up our crab cake.
Spicy ketchup.
Chili crab sauce.
Mm-hmm.
The slaw.
This is not gonna suck.
♪♪
I'm telling you what.
That's tasty.
You've got tangy,
sweet, crunchy, salty.
This is
a really nice balance.
And the kicker to the whole
thing is that slaw.
Yay.
That's ridiculous.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Wow!
Crab cake!
MAN: This thing tastes like
a really expensive crab cake.
It's delicious.
And there's more deliciousness
where that came from.
The only challenge
is pinning down
this nine-ton
tiger-striped behemoth.
MAN:
Find out wherever they are,
and have the best
gourmet lunch truck around.
FIERI: So they make it easy
with a combo
of new-school social media
and old-school technique
picked up from the
ice cream man.
[ Horn honks musically ]
That's the Chomp Chomp growl.
You hit that horn and you pull
up to an apartment complex,
people don't have to cook.
They can come out and get great,
fresh Singaporean food.
Yes.
FIERI:
Like this gourmet sandwich...
Lamb burger!
...inspired by the Little India
section of Singapore.
Delicious.
Lamb's big in Singapore?
It is.
So, we have lamb.
First is
the aromatics package.
We have mint, parsley.
Put some cilantro in there.
Dark soy sauce.
Okay.
Very Singaporean.
We've got some Worcestershire
and tamarind concentrate.
Really?
So, you've got a sweet
and a tang.
And then our spice,
mild curry powder.
Mild curry...
and hot curry.
Yep.
Chinese white pepper again,
kosher salt.
[ Whistles ]
Okay, I've got to stand
on my tippy-toes.
You're gonna fall in.
[ Chuckling ]
I know.
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger]
You gotta do it. Work harder.
It's ready to go.
[ Normal voice ] All right.
So, we make the pattie.
How many ounces?
We're doing four.
And we flat-top this?
Flat-top it.
Grill it up on both sides...
Mm-hmm.
...and make some
yogurt sauce.
Uh-huh. First ingredient
is Greek yogurt.
Got it.
Then we've got parsley,
cilantro, mint,
lime juice
freshly squeezed,
and our curry powder,
mild and the hot.
Mild and the hot.
And the kosher salt.
Mmm, smells good.
Can I taste it?
Yes.
Wow. [ Shudders ]
There's a lot going on
in there.
Our cooked lamb's done.
Nice.
Little bit of sauce.
Yogurt sauce.
Correct.
And edamame sprouts.
There we go.
♪♪
It's the last thing I expected
when I pulled up here.
I think Singapore,
I think soy sauce, Asian food,
but I'm a sucker
for a lamb burger.
The flavors
are well balanced.
I like the spicy curry.
The lamb, the herbs.
And the edamame sprouts,
I think,
are a different texture.
I love that crunch.
The sweetness,
herbaceousness of them.
The whole thing's
a package deal.
I mean, it is
a great lamb burger.
You're the bomb-dot-com.
Chomp Chomp Nation.
[ Chuckles ]
Really unique flavors.
WOMAN: Really melts in
your mouth, really tender,
lots of great spice.
Congratulations.
Awesome place.
Thank you.
I mean, a funky joint,
and you really take
a lot of appreciation,
a lot of time, a lot of care,
a lot of energy in your food.
Awesome.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
we're still soaking up
the California sun...
Ohh!
...at an outdoor pit stop...
You wanna become friends
with this cat.
...smoking up
a Southern shout-out.
This is real-deal
barbecue, man.
♪♪
So, when you're cruising
down Rosedale Highway
going East right through
the Northwest side
of Bakersfield, California,
just slow down and kind of...
hang your head out the window.
What's that you smell?
Exactly -- killer barbecue.
We're talking
mesquite-charcoaled,
some red oak, cooking up
in a funky little place
called Salty's BBQ & Catering.
♪♪
SALTERS: Half-pound
pulled pork dinner!
I give this place
a 10 and a half.
It makes me feel like
I'm back in Oklahoma.
Pig sandwich
and green beans!
The traffic's a little noisy,
but it doesn't
take away from the food.
FIERI: Which has been cooked up
curbside since 2012
by chef and owner, Jeff Salters.
You can't have a name
that cool and get
in the barbecue business.
Your last name
could be "Sauce."
That's the only name
that would be any better
than having "Salters"
as your last name.
WOMAN: It's really kind of
entertaining to watch,
knowing that that's
your chicken right there,
or that's your tri-tip.
It's great.
Salty Special!
I'm having the Salty Special.
You got
the best combination.
You got tri-tip, pulled pork,
and you got the barbecue
sauce on top of it.
FIERI:
What are we making?
We're gonna make
our Salty's rub.
We've got lemon pepper,
some garlic powder,
and then we're gonna
put in allspice.
Is there gonna be
a little seasoned salt?
A little seasoned salt, and then
we just throw a little basil.
Looks like an Indian
spice market right there.
All right. So, what are
we gonna put this on?
We're gonna put this
on our tri-tip.
We like to make
sure it's covered.
We'll leave it on overnight.
So, you're setting these up
for the next day.
We are.
Now, we're gonna rub our pork
butts with our Salty's rub.
We're gonna put them
in our smoker for 12 hours.
Then, we're gonna lay
the tri-tip out.
Got it.
We put it on by hand.
Because by foot
would be awkward?
Very.
So, this will go on
for about...
About 45 minutes.
Giddy-up.
Barbecue sauce -- What type
of barbecue sauce are you into?
Kind of a sweet,
smokey, tangy.
Ohh.
We're gonna start with
a little ketchup here,
brown sugar, hickory smoke,
soy sauce.
Worcestershire?
Worcestershire,
apple cider vinegar,
a little bit of H2O,
a little bit
of vegetable oil.
Put our yellow mustard in.
And we put a little bit
of black pepper in there.
And this is the standard sauce
for all the barbecue?
Yes, it is.
Are we gonna make
this sandwich or not?
We're gonna get there!
You're killing me, boss!
And when you have it,
it's gonna change your life.
It's gonna change my waistband
is what it's gonna change.
All right. So, now we're
gonna pull our pork butts out.
Okay.
Just check this.
Look at the bark
on that bad boy.
Nice smoke ring.
Ah, that doesn't suck.
Here we go.
[ Whistles ]
We're gonna break it down,
get it nice and chopped up.
Okay, so that's ready.
Now we grab the tri-tip
and we'll slice it.
Time to build it.
Rock and roll.
So, we're gonna start off
with laying some tri-tip out,
put a little bit of our
pulled pork in there,
put our barbecue
sauce on there,
put some yellow peppers,
top it off with a little bit
of our coleslaw.
♪♪
If you order the sandwich,
does it come with
a free beach towel
or anything like that?
Barbecue sauce is spot-on,
excellent tang,
not too much smoke.
Pulled pork's great.
Really get that deep, rich,
great flavor from the smoke.
It's a really good sauce.
Bring the kids down.
Have a sandwich for four.
This is real-deal
barbecue, man.
Nicely done.
I like that.
♪♪
The barbecue sauce
just plays off the meat.
They nailed it
with that sandwich.
You wanna find really
good barbecue,
you know what you gotta do?
You gotta find out
where super athletes eat.
Number 6, Cody Kessler,
from USC Trojans
and from Bakersfield.
When you come back, this is
one of your go-to joints?
Yeah. You know,
living in L.A.,
there's a lot
of great places to eat,
but nothing kind
of this original.
SALTERS: Pork rib dinner,
green beans, chili beans.
Jeff knows what he's doing.
I've been cooking for friends
and family for, like, 20 years.
Barbecue the whole time?
Barbecue, yeah.
Our tag is
we're the best of both worlds,
smoking and grilling.
That's smoking.
FIERI:
And this is grilling.
Half-chicken dinner,
chili beans, potato salad!
It's so tender, so moist,
and you just pick it
right off the bone.
We're gonna make chicken.
Grilled chicken.
Let's do it.
We take a whole chicken,
we split them,
put a couple slits
in there so the wings
will lay flat
when we're grilling it.
Okay.
Now we're gonna make
our marinade.
We got orange juice,
a little bit of lemon juice.
Then we put the chickens
in the marinade.
Get them nice and covered.
So, now we're gonna hit it
with the dry rub?
We're not gonna be shy
about putting it on.
You wanna cover it with foil,
let it marinate overnight.
Then we'll go to the grill.
Absolutely.
Got it.
All right. So, we've
been grilling this chicken
about 45 minutes.
We're ready to pull it off.
Hit it!
[ Whistles ]
Good-looking bird.
We just tear them by hand.
We serve them in quarters.
There's your
half-chicken dinner.
That's great bird, man.
Tender, good smoke flavor.
I like that it just
falls off the bone.
Got a little texture
in the skin.
You killed it, man.
Nice job.
♪♪
I like the crisp outside pieces,
so it's got that nice,
like, char on the outside.
The chicken is very tender.
Falls off the bone,
and its smokey flavor --
you taste a little bit
of mesquite in there.
What makes this special
is Jeff Salty.
Cool thing about this is
you're not trying
to do 10,000 things.
You're able to take it,
harness it,
do it right, and win.
Impressive.
Thank you very much.
You want to become friends
with this cat.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up on this full
hour of warm-weather hot spots,
a hidden gem
in Duck, North Carolina...
What an awesome joint.
You got to see this.
...serving seafood
on the plate...
It is decadent.
...and out the window.
MAN: Welcome to Cravings.
What can I get for you today?
♪♪
I'm here in the Outer Banks
of North Carolina
in a little town called Duck.
And I'm here
for a family reunion.
While I'm here, I gotta see
if there's any hidden
"Triple D" joints,
so I checked this place out.
It's next to a gas station,
it's got a drive-through,
but don't let those
things scare you.
They've got a great menu
and some killer seafood.
This is Cravings.
It's very fresh.
It comes right from the water
so you know you're getting
the highest-quality food.
And lobster sauce.
I really don't know a place
that I can get crab cakes
and diesel in the same location.
I'd of thought they had
lost their mind.
FIERI: But owners Dan Lewis
and Scott Foster
knew folks around Duck wouldn't
judge this book by its cover.
Or a restaurant
by a gas station?
Exactly. We basically
describe it as our version,
our take on quick service.
Ordering in, scallop dinner!
The scallops is sweet,
tender, juicy, and just fresh.
You can tell the stuff
just came out of the sea.
So, this is the beginning of
making the lobster brandy sauce.
Yes.
All right, hit it.
I take
some softened butter.
Gonna go ahead and get
some garlic in there.
Onions go in there.
Sweat the onions,
sweat the garlic.
Outer Bank sea salt.
All right.
And I go ahead and hit it
with a little bit of acid.
Make my roux now,
about three scoops of flour.
So, 50/50.
So now, I'm gonna hit it
with some wine.
♪♪
And in goes
our lobster stock.
And add some heavy cream.
Then I add the brandy.
So, we're gonna let this go,
let it reduce, hold it cold,
and then we'll use that
when we make the scallops?
Yep.
Got it.
Sauce is done.
Yeah.
Outer Bank scallops,
gorgeous-looking scallop.
Word.
Little bit of canola
and vegetable oil.
These guys just
go right in.
So, now you don't
mess with them.
You just hit them with...
No, you literally don't
want to touch them.
Let them sear
on both sides.
Little bit of that
Outer Bank salt.
Yep.
Get it seared on one side,
seared on the other side.
All right.
So, they're almost done.
Gonna go ahead
and land our sauce.
Three in the front.
Two in the back.
I'm gonna put a little dab
of truffle oil right on top.
♪♪
Fresh scallop, don't even
need to cut it with a knife.
♪♪
Dude, I'm gonna
tell you something.
This is up there in some of
the best scallops I've ever had.
'Cause this scallop
is out of bounds.
The sauce, the preparation,
the little bit of the crust
on the outside of the scallop,
super hot pan.
The touch
of the truffle oil.
It is decadent.
♪♪
I know you wish you could
try some, but I'm so sorry
about your allergy
to eating off my plate.
Mmm.
Excellent, brother.
Very nice job.
FIERI: And we're just getting
started at this joint.
Remember, we're in the
Outer Banks of North Carolina
where folks will take fresh
catch any way they can get.
MAN: Welcome to Cravings.
What can I get for you today?
Yep, even from a drive-through.
So, they can order
the whole menu?
They can get all of it?
Oh, yeah.
Not bad.
Hi, how are you today?
Good, how are you doing?
Your steamer pot's ready.
Thank you.
FIERI: It's a Carolina Coast
tradition --
a cooking pot loaded to the hilt
with fresh local seafood.
I'd say it'd feed a family
of six easily.
FIERI:
Now, that's my kind of takeout.
Wonderful way to enjoy
the local fare.
You said that
very newscaster-ish.
♪♪
[ Deep voice ]
Enjoy the local fare.
[ Normal voice ] All right.
So, tell us what we do.
We start out with
a little bit of ice.
Ice is in the bottom
so it keeps it cold,
and it also works as
the steaming liquid
for when this gets going?
Exactly. And if you wanna
throw a beer or wine
in there,
that's your pleasure.
Live on the edge.
Exactly.
Cut red potatoes,
smoked sausage.
What kind of sausage?
This is a smoked sausage
from a guy named Larry
in Fayetteville,
and of course, it's called
Larry's sausage.
Next, we have our fresh
local corn on the cob.
We have some wonderful
Eastern Shore oysters,
middleneck clams,
and of course,
some crab legs.
Believe it or not,
snow crab legs
are very popular
in the Outer Banks.
We also have the fresh
local shrimp.
Now, the reason I'm packing
them in a plastic bag
is because you don't
want to cook the shrimp
the same amount of time
as you do the...
They'll be tough
as can be.
Exactly.
What is that seasoning
there?
That is Old Bay,
of course.
Okay.
And butter and cocktail
to go along with.
Put the lid on it?
Lid on, and this
is how it goes home.
Can you get this one
rolling?
Okay.
Oh!
Hello.
Takes about 20 minutes
for the ice to melt.
But once it starts steaming,
it takes roughly
about a half-hour.
And the shrimp go in
about halfway through,
so again, the shrimp
are not overcooked.
Got it.
And so,
we're ready to go.
Get yourself a big tray,
just let everything
pour right out.
Oh, look at the broth.
Oh, the broth
is fantastic.
The shellfish broth,
the shrimp broth,
you got all that sausage.
The sausage just flavors
the potatoes so well.
Okay. So, the idea is throw
it down on the table, crack it.
♪♪
Mmm.
Little bit of lemon juice.
Something about shrimp
that's not been frozen, mmm.
Oh, yeah. There's nothing like
the fresh local shrimp.
[ Typewriter clicking ]
Ding!
Mnh, mnh! Ding!
There's a lot going on here.
Four big pieces of sausage,
potatoes, the corn.
♪♪
Excellent. And you didn't
even have to get out of your car
to get it?
No, you can get it right through
the drive-through if you like.
Package deal, man.
Ordering in,
steamer pot for six.
Here's your steamer pot.
WOMAN: It's so simple to do.
Throw it on your stove
and you're done.
You've got a fresh,
local seafood feast.
Gentlemen, thanks
for having me, man.
Thanks for being here.
What an awesome joint.
You gotta see this.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next,
we're hitting the desert
in Tempe, Arizona...
Whoo! Thanks for
the warning on that one!
...for a surprising spot...
You're gonna love it.
...putting out perfect
Pakistani.
That is some of the best chicken
we've ever had on "Triple D."
I'm not kidding you.
♪♪
I'm here at Tempe, Arizona,
right across the street
from Arizona State,
home of the Sun Devils,
to check out some food
you'd expect in Arizona --
Mexican.
I'm here at Los...
No, Dos...
Oh, no, that's
a different place!
I'm here to check out some
Pakistani food at this joint,
the Curry Corner.
♪♪
-Shrimp Handi.
-It's a gem.
MAN: I would've never expected
to find an authentic
Pakistani restaurant
in a shopping center.
I travelled to Pakistan,
and I lived there for two years.
And this is just like
what I used to eat there.
In the world of Pakistani food,
this is 100% legit?
101% legit.
101% legit?
FIERI: So is Farah Khalid,
who grew up in the
Punjab region of Pakistan.
And after travelling the world
with her husband,
they settled in Tempe...
Tandoori chicken tikka
ready!
...where she's been pushing
the culinary envelope
since 2002.
Food all across the board
is fantastic here.
They cook it in
a traditional tandoori oven,
which is really unique.
It's a blazing-hot clay oven
cranking out
this Indian and Pakistani
classic.
Tandoori chicken tikka.
Rich and spicy, but not hot.
FIERI: And flavored
with the righteous spice mix
called garam masala.
Holy nutmeg, Batman!
All of these
are going in there?
Yes.
All right.
So, let's get it going.
Green cardamom,
whole nutmeg.
All the nutmeg?
Black pepper, cloves,
white cumin seeds.
What is this?
Dried apricot.
It looks like dried apricot.
This is the whole mace.
It's very strong.
Yeah, you're telling me.
[ Laughs ]
[ Coughs ] Whoo!
Thanks for the warning
on that one!
Black cardamom, bay leaves.
The nutmeg beans are that
big, and nutmeg is so hard,
she goes through about
one of these every week.
Okay. So, now we have
the Garam Masala.
Okay. And now we are going
to do the chicken tikka.
Ginger garlic.
Pureed ginger
and pureed garlic.
Yes. Lemon juice, oil,
and yellow food color.
Really? Number 5?
I don't like it the tandoori
very, very red.
No, I don't like it
that much.
Tomato puree, the salt,
chili powder, cayenne powder,
and last we are
using Garam Masala.
You can smell it.
Oh, no.
I know that joke.
That's super potent.
Be careful.
[ Laughter ]
Is it good?
I didn't taste it yet!
You taste it!
It's ready to go.
Oh, that's not,
"Be careful."
That's,
"You're gonna love it."
Ohh!
The chicken leg
is the best.
You gotta go
with that dark meat.
So, a little score so the sauce
will get down in there.
And we're going to skewer
that onto this?
Yes.
[ Swish! Swish! Swish! ]
♪♪
Okay. So, we get all
the sauce in there,
let it go for overnight.
All right. So, now you go
in, around, down,
skewer it though.
Yes.
How many pieces will
you put on a skewer?
Two pieces in one order.
Okay. It's going in
the tandoor?
Yes.
So, 15 minutes?
Yeah.
♪♪
Yeah!
Thank you.
Is that ghee,
or is that butter?
It's the butter.
Now, this is the cilantro.
And now you are
going to taste it.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
It's good?
This is out of bounds.
Super rich flavor,
little bit of spice,
little bit of ginger,
little bit of garlic,
roasted down to where
it's just starting
to separate,
come off the bone.
And smoking hot that is.
Wow!
That is some
of the best chicken
we've ever had on "Triple D."
I'm not kidding you.
Oh-ho!
It's really tender,
a little spicy, tastes amazing.
We had them cater
his second birthday party.
Some Pakistani food
for my kid's second birthday.
We'll do a whole-hog
barbecue for your fifth.
FIERI: Or a whole goat,
like the Pakistanis do.
In Pakistan, goat is
a very common food.
So, what are we making?
We are making
the goat karahi.
I'm going to boil the goat
and ginger-garlic,
salt, bay leaves,
black pepper,
and a little bit of cloves.
And then water.
Cook it down for how long?
It takes, like,
30 minutes.
What does "karahi" mean?
Karahi means the wok.
Do you use a wok
a lot in Pakistani cooking?
Yes. The ginger-garlic.
Ginger-garlic mix.
What is this
magnificent mixture?
This is
an onion-based puree.
So, I'm going to put
a little bit of that.
Place the tomatoes inside.
♪♪
And I am going to cover it.
How long's that go?
This goes like
10 minutes.
It becomes more, you know,
tender and more juicy.
So it really cooks down.
And now we are going
to do the naan for you.
N-A-A-N?
N-A-A-N.
Let's start with yogurt,
milk, dry yeast,
baking powder,
sugar, oil, eggs,
salt, flour.
So, we are going to make
one garlic and one cheese.
♪♪
This is the garlic naan.
This is going to be
a cheese naan.
Okay.
[ Texan accent ]
We call that a quesadilla.
♪♪
And that's it,
right on the side?
You want to try that?
Yeah!
I'm down with it.
Okay, right up here?
-Oh.
-Too high?
-No, I think it's okay.
-Okay.
Look at that thing puffing.
And now you are
going to do it.
Aah!
Excellent job!
Huh, what do you think?
Let's see our goat karahi.
Now I'm going to
put the yogurt in it.
Ground cumin, coriander,
black pepper,
little bit of salt,
sliced ginger,
green chilies,
fresh cilantro.
The most important part --
the butter.
♪♪
And then we will put a little
bit more cilantro on the top
and a little bit
more ginger.
Right. So, we got the garlic
naan and the cheese naan.
♪♪
There's the one with cheese.
That's the cheese.
Mmm.
Are you supposed to
eat this by hand?
No, you can use a fork.
Mmm. Now you tell me.
Oh, my gosh.
The goat cooked down like that,
it's super tender.
A little bit of the spiciness
to the creaminess.
Reduction of the sauce,
the fresh cilantro in there,
all those little nuances
come together.
Ah, I can't stop!
♪♪
All-around delicious dish.
It's spicy and always fresh.
MAN: There's many different
options for ethnic food
down here, but this is the one
that I keep coming back to.
This is the flavor temple.
You live in Arizona
anywhere close to Phoenix,
you haven't checked
this place out,
you are missing it.
Awesome.
-Thank you.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
in Pasadena, Florida...
I put on 30 pounds
since I've been here!
...a decades-old
beach town treasure...
Look at you, man!
You are a machine!
...where their special spin
is the smoke.
Who would've thunk?
♪♪
I'm here cruising the beach area
in St. Petersburg, Florida,
right outside of Tampa.
Now, the reason I'm here
is because
so many of you
have e-mailed me,
telling me about this joint
I just gotta check out --
Ted Peters Famous Smoked Fish.
Nice call.
Can't you smell it?
[ Sniffs ]
It's a smokehouse over there.
WOMAN: The very first time
we came, he bought me
one of those
smoked mackerel pieces.
Romantic.
The salmon -- It's so good.
Grab a fork.
Mmm.
I put on 30 pounds
since I've been here!
Thanks to the e-mailers
who got me down here.
You can just sit back,
relax, enjoy your meal.
This is, like,
fifth generation.
The place itself has been
family-run for 56 years.
Co-owner Michael Lathrop's
uncle was the guy
with his name on the sign
and the good idea
to turn a backyard hobby,
smoking fish,
into a business.
Yeah, Ted Peters.
He took it from the backyard,
stuck it out
in the front yard,
and kind of waved the traffic
down as it would go by.
And people would put
the brakes on, back up,
and say,
"What's that about?"
Today, folks are still jamming
on the brakes for smoked salmon,
mahimahi, and the hometown
favorite, mullet.
In here, through
the John Wayne doors?
Yep.
Still made the same way
by the same family.
This is our fishmonger
for the day?
Ben,
he's fifth-generation here.
Nice to meet you.
It's like a piece of history.
I just shook
the Liberty Bell.
[ Laughs ]
So, what I'm gonna do
is run some salt
light over all the fish.
And then, we'll put
our mixture on all of them.
And what is the mixture?
Our secret sauce.
Well, you gotta give me
a basis of it.
Are we tomato based
in here? Are we...
Yeah, tomato base.
I can see oil in it.
But you're not stirring it up.
You're not putting a lot on.
No, it's just real light
just to keep it from burning,
give it a little color.
Just pick it up
by the tray here.
Just slide it in the cart and
take it over to the smokehouse.
I've never taken my smoked fish
for a walk before.
All right. Just take the tray
and slide it in there.
So, I guess that you have
be a family member
or you have to have
the eagle-span reach.
Did you see that?
MICHAEL: Yeah, little guys
don't do this well.
What are we smoking with?
This is red oak.
What's going to happen
in a few minutes,
you're going to have such
a concentration of smoke
in there that
it's gonna be equally
seeping out of all the trays.
Do they go in at a certain
location to start with?
Yeah. You want the raw
fish on the bottom.
And as you add,
you raise up.
You don't just set it
and forget it.
You actually have to be
participating every 15 minutes,
pulling the rack,
looking where you're at,
seeing how things
are moving along.
You guys ever heard
about second-hand smoke?
FIERI: Next stop's
the cooling cabinet
and they're ready to serve.
They got the best
smoked fish there is around.
And now they have salmon,
which is unbelievable.
Smoked mullet's
really good, too.
♪♪
That's tasty.
Who would've thunk?
FIERI: And who'd have
thunk up this one?
It's a top seller --
smoked fish all chopped up
into Ted Peters'
legendary fish spread.
Be sure to order
the fish spread.
I hear out of everything
at Ted Peters, this is, like,
the spread is, like,
the kicker.
This is the thing.
So, what is made
in the fish spread?
That is mahi and mullet.
The mullet is the kicker
to the spread, though.
The --
Can't use my --
That's my word!
I wondered where
I heard it from.
Okay. So, you break
it down by hand.
Then it goes into
this grinder
to make sure
that it's uniform size.
Exactly.
So, what you want to do
is you want
to get it fluffy as you can.
Now, we're gonna
add celery and onion.
Celery and onion.
Pickle relish.
It's sweet relish.
You're gonna mix 'em again.
It's always by hand?
It's always by hand.
Okay.
Now, the salad dressing.
It holds it together.
This definitely,
you gotta shoulder muscles for.
Look at you, man!
You are a machine!
♪♪
What pulls that
all together --
the onion,
the celery,
and the smoke.
That's really good,
actually.
FIERI: You can get the fish
spread on a sandwich,
but lots of folks get it as part
of the meal locals know as...
The Ted Peters
surf and turf.
You eat the fish spread,
and then, that's the fish.
And then you eat the hamburger,
and that's the...
That's the surf and turf.
Their cheeseburgers are great.
That's a real burger.
That is.
The cheese, it always
stays melted,
so it's always,
like, extra gooey.
Besides, where else
can you eat on plates
that remind you of your
elementary school cafeteria?
You're right.
[ Laughter ]
And to round out
the total Ted Peters experience,
the locals have
one more suggestion.
Be sure and get
the warm potato salad.
And now we take the bacon.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hot grease and all?
Yes.
Mmm, that is up
there in the top
best potato salads
I've ever had.
FIERI: Fits right in
with the surf and turf
and the smoked mullet.
I love smoked mullet.
I've never had anything else
here, to tell you the truth.
And the whole Ted Peters thing
that folks around here
have been coming back
for since 1951.
I had my first
smoked mullet
about 30 years ago
at this place.
How long have you
been coming here?
25 years.
Were you in a stroller?
Yes.
So many people look at us
as not the owners,
but the caretakers of something
that's part theirs,
because this restaurant
in this area
is the last thing that anchors
their childhood memories.
And did you think that sending
in an e-mail to Food Network
for "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
was gonna turn into this?
I need to stop sitting up
at 2:00 in the morning
half-asleep and tapping
on the keyboard.
[ Laughter ]
I have to say thanks, man.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry, we got
plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking
for you next time,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If that was
an '80s rock star,
that would be "Naan" Jovi.
[Bon]
[ Laughter ]
Naan Jovi!
♪♪