Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Hello.
...we're cruising towards
some delicious detours.
Look at that.
Like a two-for-one
in Norfolk, Virginia.
I want to have
my birthday party here.
Revving up a butchery by day...
One of a kind joint
you've got to check out.
...then taking a Flavortown
U-turn at night.
Ridiculous.
Like, ridiculous good.
And here's a doozy for you.
Doctor.
A legit German-Swiss joint...
I think Hofbrau
and Schnitzel Emporium.
...smack-dab
in the middle of Maui.
I didn't see that
coming, everybody.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in
Norfolk, Virginia,
and check this story out.
Husband and wife team
buy this old house,
and they convert it
into a butcher shop.
Well then they turn it
into a restaurant.
Well then they rent it out
to another guy
to do a restaurant at night.
That's my kind
of Triple-D joint.
This is Pendulum.
There's not another
butcher shop like Pendulum.
We have a flat-iron
steak back here.
You can come buy all different
kinds of meats here,
great sausages.
Or you can get a sandwich
and eat it here.
Pick it up,
two Monte Cristos.
FIERI: And the crazy thing is
owner Dylan Wakefield's journey
to making sandwiches
actually started on a sub.
I was in the navy on
a submarine for 8 years,
cooking underwater.
And then went
to culinary school.
FIERI: And where did you
learn to butcher?
A little bit
in culinary school
and a lot of it
just on the job.
You can see your sausages being
made, or your meat being cut,
or your sandwiches
being made.
MAN: Pick it up,
one roast beef with fries.
You can't go wrong
with the roast beef sandwich.
I keep ordering this
'cause it's so good.
So what are we gonna
break out of here?
What I use for our
butcher's roast beef
sandwich is a top round.
Tender, lean, cooks great,
slices awesome.
Yep.
Yep, yeah.
So on the exterior layer
I'll just be cutting off
good fat to go
into rendering.
And I'm really try to expose
some of the seams.
There we go.
Yahtzee!
Get this
top round out.
Yep.
FIERI: And then,
the real fun begins.
This is a gigantic
playground.
I want to have
my birthday party here.
You have
all the toys.
This gigantic
caveman smoker.
Yeah.
These old butcher
paper rolls.
Let me see that
butcher twine.
There's room
in my shirt.
Don't worry,
I can get it in here.
Ridiculous. Aw!
So part of using
that whole animal,
this is the fat
we just ground up.
Yep.
We're gonna make
this into oil,
so any time we're
using the griddle
we want to use
a little bit of tallow.
We throw some
garlic and rosemary
in there just for flavor,
and then we render
this down really slowly.
And it's almost
like a confit.
That's awesome.
Don't be shallow
about the tallow.
Yes.
So here is the top
round that you cut.
The butcher's recipe.
Hence the butcher
and the roast beef. So.
Salt, pepper, garlic,
red onions.
Just a nice
paste here.
Now do you tie it first,
or do you rub it first?
I do need to tie it.
Somebody took my string.
[ Sighs ]
It's in my car.
I was holding it over there
so it didn't get dirty.
Okay.
Nobody told me
we needed it.
All right. So I'm gonna
do a pretty quick tie-up.
Spot me right there.
It keeps everything
a little bit
more contained,
and doesn't dry out.
Doctor?
All right.
Where's that bag.
So now we get this rub
of the garlic
and the shallots,
salt and the pepper.
And then we sell it by
the pound or on a sandwich.
You're not for real.
In the oven,
what temp?
There we go.
We keep that at 350,
let it rest,
get it nice and cold so they
actually slice really well.
Look at that.
So thin, it only
has one side.
This is for science.
Yes.
Nice.
I really believe, especially
on these tougher pieces of meat,
the thinner you can slice it,
the better.
Like, pit beef that you
get up in Baltimore.
Shout out to Chaps.
If you ever get the chance
to go to Chaps Pit Beef,
trust me, you'll love it.
But this right here, bro.
You're right in there.
And this gets what?
Caramelized onions,
Swiss cheese on there.
And that's gonna
go in the oven.
Tallow,
focaccia grilled off.
Every day you're making
a batch of bread?
Every day.
Man, you can totally smell
the rosemary and garlic.
We're gonna smear
with spicy mayo.
We're gonna take
that roast beef
that just came
out of the oven.
I'm having full
flashbacks on this.
The roast beef sandwich at the
meat market when I was a kid.
The meat was roasted there,
sliced thin.
You can really appreciate
the craftsmanship,
time, the energy,
the effort
that were all utilized
to make that sandwich.
It's worth everything
that you're getting.
Don't touch this.
All mine.
...roast beef.
It's just really juicy,
and it has the right amount
of crisp on the top of it.
The onions add the perfect
note of tanginess.
WOMAN: This place is great
for a sandwich,
and then you realize, "Wait a
minute, I'm also in a market."
There are so many things
going on here.
They even have classes
on how to butcher.
Superman, you do knife
sharpening here also?
WAKEFIELD: Yes.
I'm done with you.
WOMAN: It's just different than
any other type of restaurant
or market
that you might see.
What I want my walk-in
to look like.
Some of our house-cured
hams on the bone.
We cure and smoke
ham and bacon.
Are you human?
FIERI:
And this hand-crafted pork
is piled high on
a classic Havana sandwich.
Cuban with fries.
Now we're gonna get
into a Cuban sandwich.
Yeah.
Take a pork leg,
break it down.
Cut it into all
the individual muscles.
Now we're gonna
rub them.
Salt,
pepper, garlic.
Kind of making
that wet paste.
In the old smoke pit.
How long are you
gonna smoke?
Four hours,
175 to 200 degrees.
As low as you
can get it.
This is our rested
and ready-to-slice-up pork.
Looking for that beautiful
pink smoke ring.
There you go.
What kind of smoke
are you using on that?
I like the oily pecan.
Thin slices.
Beautiful.
They can buy this
in the deli case?
Yes.
Ridiculous.
Put some cheese on there.
This goes in the oven
and gets warmed up.
Really good
flatbread again.
Spicy mustard.
That's hot.
That is hot.
Where are the pickles
coming from?
Just a regular pickle
that we get.
You didn't make something,
you slacker!
The only thing
I got on this guy.
Press that down
really good.
A classic Cuban.
Good.
Very seldom are you able
to get meat like that
because Captain America
is butchering it down,
separating the muscles
on that hind-quarter,
and then making it available
just sliced thin.
That's why this doesn't
have any of that fat.
Yeah.
This isn't
a pulled-pork.
Wow!
Brother, I'm glad
I don't live in Norfolk.
We'd probably
be friends.
I'd probably
be over here.
Yeah, I know, man.
It wouldn't be
swimsuit season ever.
This is by far one of the best
Cuban sandwiches I've had.
Pork has got an amazing
smokey essence to it.
Everything's done and made
with, you know, great pride.
It's just a fantastic place.
Superman, this experience
that I've had
has been
unforgettable.
And thank you for your
service to our country.
That means so much.
I'm telling you right now,
one-of-a-kind joint
you've got
to check out.
Thank you so much.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next, we're staying
surprisingly close by...
Very nice.
...where things
are getting
sticky with the wings...
Tastes like
something good?
That tastes like
something great.
...and righteous
with the ramen.
You don't want to eat
it too fast 'cause you
don't want it to end.
We want to support
our local farmer,
and we want to go over
and be able to eat...
Oh, no. Now you're
grabbing a big one.
Now that's a knife.
Oh, yes it is.
♪♪
So you guys ready
to continue this
Norfolk culinary experience?
This next place we're
gonna check out,
a young chef has taken
Asian street food
to another level.
You ready to roll?
Let's hit it.
♪♪
We're here.
This is Alkaline.
Yep, this joint is
in the same big house
as the last place we visited,
and you got it,
they share the same kitchen.
Spicy red curry, runner, please.
MAN: Pendulum is here
during the day,
and then Alkaline
opens up at night
serving ramen
and street food.
Crispy baby octopus
and shrimp.
So how long does it take you
to change over the kitchen
from Pendulum
to Alkaline?
The kitchen's
pretty smooth.
The front of the house
is a little bit hairier.
You have a hairy
front of the house?
Yeah.
That's got
to be sightly.
FIERI: And covering the PM shift
is chef and owner,
Kevin Ordonez, dishing out
his brand of Asian fusion.
ORDONEZ: Asian sticky wings,
runner, please.
Everywhere you can find,
like, buffalo wings.
But you've got to come here
to get these Asian sticky wings.
WOMAN: It's crispy
on the outside.
It's tender, it's juicy.
All right, what
are we gonna make?
Asian sticky wings.
We're gonna make
the batter first.
Smile, what's
the batter?
[ Rim shot ]
It's pretty much
potato starch...
Nothing?
Did you get
the joke?
Well I'm short, so, you know,
things go over my head.
[ Rim shot ]
[ Laughs ]
Touché.
Potato starch.
AP Flour, Japanese
spice blend.
Got you.
Granulated garlic,
and the water is not measured.
We just pour enough
to make a nice, loose batter.
Just so we get a nice
little slurry going.
Yep.
So now we're gonna take
our chicken wings,
and I'm just gonna dredge
in some more potato starch
before it goes
into the batter.
All right.
I'm just gonna hold them
in the fryer a little bit.
That way they don't
stick to the bottom.
I slip these up sort
of closer to the surface,
and I just
sprinkle them in.
So that extra little
drizzle drizzle...
Some little
crunchy bits.
So those go for 8 minutes,
pull them up, let them rest,
drop them
for another two.
And in the mean time,
what are we gonna do?
We're gonna go ahead
and make the sauce.
Dig it.
We got some ketchup here,
mayo, sriracha, honey...
Darling.
Sweetie.
...water, chili oil,
some Worcestershire,
and this
is called tare,
which is essentially
a seasoned soy sauce.
Very nice.
Now we pull the wings?
Yeah.
Spend all that time
trying to make them crunchy,
if I pour all that sauce,
it's just gonna sog them up.
So I brush each wing.
Do you only
serve this dish?
'Cause the amount of time
that you take on this one dish,
buddy, you know,
we got people waiting.
Some scallions in here
and some fried garlic.
Finish with a little
sesame seeds.
Asian sticky wings.
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
Tastes like
something good?
That tastes like
something great.
Awesome.
The sauce
is on point.
You go to a degree
of extra effort
just to not have them
turn to complete sog
'cause if you did
toss them in the sauce
we wouldn't be
getting that crunch.
A lot of balance,
good techniques.
That is awesome.
SERVER: Asian sticky wings?
WOMAN: They're just
the right amount of spicy,
a little bit of sweet.
It's like a potato chip, like,
wrapped around a wing.
Me lovey wingy.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
WOMAN #2: Kevin, he's
a very talented chef.
Very creative.
Where did you
learn to cook?
Classically trained
in New York.
Did your family
cook though?
No, not
professionally.
We were stationed in Japan
for about 6 years
when I
was younger.
That had to
be terrible.
FIERI: Which lead to his love
for righteous ramen,
which he's serving up here
in all kinds of ways.
Taiwanese beef noodle soup,
runner, please.
The oxtail is
definitely my favorite.
It's got that nice
beef bone broth.
It's got complex flavors.
What's the game?
We're gonna
make oxtail here
for our oxtail
noodle soup.
I'm gonna hit it with
some salt and pepper first.
Okay, so we're gonna
sear these off.
Yep.
We're gonna make
our own braising liquid.
Got some cinnamon,
dried chilies, star anise,
some black peppercorns,
cloves and some Sichuan
peppercorns.
Love them.
Get them toasted,
let them get aromatic.
This is tare.
Tare, the roasted
chicken bones...
Yep.
...simmered in
the soy sauce.
Really the flavor
is crazy.
This is Chinese
cooking wine.
Got some chili
paste here.
A little bit of water,
some rice vinegar, ginger here
and one head of garlic.
And then our sachet,
our little packet.
Give it a little tie.
Cover this with foil,
throw it in the oven,
350 for about
5 to 6 hours.
All right, home slice.
You roasted the beef bones.
Yep. Smother them with
some tomato paste.
These are gonna go
back in the oven?
Yep.
About 10 minutes.
Okay.
Now I'm gonna go ahead
and toss them in this pot,
and fill it up with the
vegetables and some water.
Everybody
in the pool?
Simmer it
for 48 hours.
And then you have 7,000 other
ingredients to put together.
I'm gonna go ahead and start
by sautéing some cabbage.
The oxtail, start
assembling the bowl.
This is something
called beef tare,
and it's like a reduced version
of the braising liquid.
Okay.
Katsubushi salt,
smoked and dried tuna that's
been shaved super thin.
We blend it with some sea salt
and some beef fat.
Chili garlic oil that
we make here in house.
Black vinegar.
I'm gonna go ahead
and drop the noodles down,
and get them cooking.
So this is our
strained beef broth.
Oh.
The noodles
should be done.
We'll take a little bit
of the oxtail,
cabbage, scallions,
beef tendon that
we've cooked and sliced,
cilantro.
Finish with some sesame seeds,
some cilantro oil.
That's a lot of time,
energy, and love.
The depth of the broth
is ridiculous.
You got this really
phenomenal, tender,
super flavorful oxtail.
Then I get
the tender noodle.
Then I get that little bite
of the cabbage.
Then I get some of that
fresh green onion.
Then I'm over there into
a little bit of the spice.
Then I get some
of that cilantro oil.
You don't want
to eat it too fast
'cause you don't
want it to end.
Like, seriously, bro.
It's legit.
-Noodles in 3 minutes.
-Heard that.
It's very rich, and the beef
bone broth is just perfect.
If I could just, like, swim
in it, that would be awesome.
Korean barbecue
short ribs, runner.
I love Alkaline.
It's become sort of
comfort food for us.
We never leave here hungry.
Watch out for this guy.
He's gonna take over.
Ridiculous.
Like, ridiculous good.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
we're headed to Maui...
I like that touch.
...to a spot swapping
the typical seafood...
Ohh!
...for some strudel
and spaetzle shenanigans.
Give me five.
[ Laughs ]
Spaetzle brothers.
♪♪
So I'm here in Maui
in a not-so-traditional place,
looking for a, well,
not-so-traditional restaurant.
Because, you know, once in
a while you kind of get tired
of all that fresh,
off-the-boat awesome seafood,
and that delicious island fare.
Well maybe you don't, but you're
looking for some German food,
and you're here at Brigit
& Bernard's Garden Café.
WEBER: Swiss Brat
platter special.
An amazing hidden secret.
Wiener schnitzel.
I recommend it to every
person that I meet.
It's one of a kind,
of course, on this island.
Guten appetit.
In all of Hawaii?
In all of Hawaii.
FIERI: Swiss-born chef,
Bernard Weber,
had been cooking
all over the world
when he landed
in Hawaii by chance.
I was on my way back
to Australia,
and I stop
in Honolulu,
and I met Brigit
and I haven't left.
Brigit and Bernard
ended up divorcing,
but they've stuck together
at their namesake restaurant
for over 20 years.
Whatever Bernard makes
is authentic.
Beef rouladen.
Rouladen is a very
traditional dish.
It's braised beef rolled up
with different ingredients.
And then
the spaetzle noodles.
So what are
we gonna make?
Beef rouladen is a German,
northern Swiss dish,
and we're gonna use
an eye of round.
Slice off really
nice, thin pieces.
And then we
doctor it up.
Okay, doctor.
With the Dijon mustard,
raw bacon, slightly smoked.
In the middle?
Then we use kosher
dill pickle,
sliced thin,
the caramelized onions.
We're gonna use
some tweezers, actually.
[ German accent ]
Tweezers?
Yeah.
[ normal voice ]
Thank goodness you
have the tweezers.
Now we roll them
as tight as we can.
This is the seasoning
on the outside?
Yes. Salt, pepper
and Hungarian paprika.
That's tasty.
Oven sear for 20 minutes.
They're gonna
be firmed up.
And then we put them
in a hotel pan,
add some red wine
and some jus.
And then we simmer them
in the oven
for 45 minutes
and you're ready to go.
You're gonna make spaetzle.
I love spaetzle.
Water.
Eggs.
A little oil.
Oil.
Nutmeg.
I like that touch.
Paprika and a whole lot
of unbleached flour.
Unbleached?
Really makes it al dente.
Unbleached.
So you just go like this.
So classy.
You just
start pressing.
There you go.
And then you lift it up,
and they break.
Not your
first rodeo.
And you see they're already
popping to the top.
And those you can take.
Cold water.
Impressed.
I've seen a lot of spaetzle
a lot of ways.
This might be one
of my favorite.
There you go.
You want me to
do it this time?
If you want to.
Doctor.
Okay. I get to work
the prep shift.
-Lift up.
-Okay.
There you go.
Give me five.
[ Laughs ]
Spaetzle brothers.
FIERI: So what are we
gonna make now?
Really old European dish,
braised red cabbage.
So onions, garlic, bay leaf,
nutmeg, sugar, clove.
White vinegar,
red wine, and water.
We're just gonna let
this cook down for how long?
45 minutes.
Maestro?
Maestro.
And this is one
of the number-one sellers.
That is definitely one
♪♪
Mm.
How far are we
from the beach?
Walking,
half an hour.
You're gonna need it.
[ Laughs ]
The meat really cooks down
to where it's almost
like shredded pot roast.
There's a nice crust
on the outside of it.
Caramelized onions
are awesome.
You need the acidity
of the dill pickle.
A little bit of touch
of the mustard, of course.
The cabbage is
the perfect complement.
The spaetzle is stupid.
I'm just gonna
order a side of spaetzle.
I've had a lot
of German food.
I was in Munich.
I would still be in Munich
if I had had this.
What a nice dish, chef.
Rouladen is ready.
It's so delicious.
I grew up in a German
family in Detroit,
and it shocked me to find
rouladen so great, and on Maui.
Pork tenderloin
à la Bernard.
It does make me feel as if
I have gone back to Germany.
You're never not entertained
by the wall decor.
And small beer.
That's the beginner's size.
Just after breakfast.
Much more than that
would be ridiculous.
One of the best things about
this restaurant is the chef.
He's full of character.
FIERI: And grit.
You just battled cancer
recently.
Yeah, a year ago.
And you're back in it.
I was back
6 months later.
You're a warrior.
Just very passionate
about what he does,
and makes it a special place
to come back to.
All right.
What's the next dish we have?
Next thing we're
gonna make --
No, don't tell me.
Hang on.
We're hanging out in Maui
with the man having
the real-deal experience.
We come back we're
gonna make...
Something big.
We're gonna make
something big.
[ German accent ]
With the tweezers!
[ Normal voice ]
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're hanging out in Maui.
We're at Brigit
& Bernard's Garden Café.
Garden Café?
Garden Café.
I think Hofbrau
and Schnitzel Emporium.
Guten appetit.
There is no other German
restaurant here on Maui.
It's like a little jewel.
All right. What are we
making next, chef?
We are gonna make
an apple strudel.
A traditional strudel.
Apple strudel.
The old-fashioned way.
Okay.
This is one of those desserts
that I look forward to.
It's a really good, flaky crust
that has apples on the inside.
This vanilla cream
sauce on top
is absolutely delightful.
All right.
Let's get it going.
We're gonna start
with some milk, oil,
some eggs,
a little salt.
Let me guess.
Unbleached flour.
There you go.
So we let this mix.
Put it in film wrap
and let it sit there overnight.
And then we'll
roll it out.
[ Laughs ] Hey!
That is a lot
of dough, bro.
Hello.
The mixture, some apples.
I put some sugar in, cinnamon.
Then use macadamia nuts
or hazel nuts.
A lot of macadamia nuts up
in the Swiss Alps.
No, we have a lot
over here.
Raisins.
There you go.
Then we lay it
on there.
Go like this, about
a half into the middle.
Lay it in.
Okay.
Then we take
the cheese cloth.
Ohhh!
Oh, dude,
that is awesome.
I didn't see that coming,
everybody.
And then we use
some egg wash.
Throw it in the oven,
45 minutes at 325.
And what are we gonna
serve it with?
Vanilla bean sauce.
Swiss vanilla bean sauce
is what I was hoping for.
It's fresh milk, sugar,
fresh vanilla bean.
The whole bean itself?
And lemon skin.
Let that come
to a boil.
In the mean time, you have
milk with a little bit
of corn starch
and some egg yolks.
Oh, there we go.
And that's gonna tighten
that up, cream that up.
Then you'll strain it.
And cool it off.
Look at that.
Right out
of the oven.
Huh?
With whipping cream
and a strawberry for garnish.
Powdered sugar.
And then we take the ice-cold
vanilla bean sauce
over the hot strudel.
And here we go.
A lot of times I think
of strudel as being light.
The dough has more
texture than I expected.
The filling
is fantastic.
And it's just like
you got ice cream
with the vanilla sauce.
Yeah.
It's nice and creamy, luxurious,
but it's not overly sweet.
I like the crust
of apple pie.
That's my favorite part.
So if you like a real
hearty crust,
this is your dessert.
So incredibly delicious.
It's a perfect dessert.
Brigit!
We're so lucky to have Bernard
and Brigit here.
One of the best
restaurants on the island.
I wanted something
different.
Something that wasn't just
the traditional
what I would get
every time in Maui,
this is about as far of
a change as you can get.
I'm impressed.
Aloha.
Alo -- And then he
gives me aloha.
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
of some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
Are there locks
on the meat case now?
No, but maybe they
should put some on.
You keep
it quiet.
What do you want out of there?
I saw some T-bones.