Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That's not hot at all.
Bird is the word...
That's how you do it.
...along with some
big-time beef.
Tell me I didn't get you
anything nice for your birthday.
Which means you got to grab
some Texas brisket...
You don't even need
a knife with that.
You can cut that
with a bad look.
KNIGHT: Beautiful.
FIERI: ...at a joint that's also
dishing out the duck.
I thought it
was gonna be good.
This is fantastic.
Plus some meaty Mexican
in Phoenix...
My mouth is
starting to drool.
...and a comfort food kitchen
in Colorado...
This'll set you free,
brother.
This will set you free.
...taking flight with their
off-the-chain chicken.
It's a chicken train
going to Flavortown.
Whoo-whoo!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Phoenix,
Arizona, right off highway 51
and about five minutes
from downtown.
Kind of an
industrial park area --
There's a lot of cars
moving by really fast.
Now, if there's ever been a time
I've told you to slow down
and take a look around,
it's now.
Had a couple "Triple D" chefs
call me and say,
"You got to check
this joint out.
This is Tacos Chiwas.
[ Sizzles ]
Tres el pastor tacos here.
I've had hundreds of tacos
at Tacos Chiwas.
WOMAN: This reminds me of the
kind of good street food
that you get down in Mexico.
FIERI: 'Cause husband-and-wife
team Armando Hernandez
and Nadia Holguin
are introducing
the people of Arizona
the flavors from their home
state of Chihuahua.
What is Chihuahuan food?
How would you describe it?
HOLGUIN: Smoky, spicy.
Chihuahua's landlocked, so it
has a lot to do with proteins,
a lot of flour.
Barbacoa
tacos, order it.
I'm having the two
tacos of barbacoa.
It's really tender,
a lot of bold flavors.
Everybody's got
their own barbacoa.
What makes this so good?
HOLGUIN:
We use beef cheek...
These cheeks,
by the way --
these guys here,
not the other cheeks.
...Anaheim chilies.
Tomates?
Tomates, and a little bit
of cebolla, garlic,
bay leaves,
black pepper.
Salt.
Then we're gonna put it
in the smoker overnight, 300.
Typically when people are
making barbacoa in Chihuahua,
are they doing it
in smokers?
No. Underground.
So, you're kind of doing
your adaptation.
All right,
what do we do next?
We're making
the salsa roja.
Roasted tomato,
Chile De Arbol.
Well, that's a bunch
of Chile De Arbol.
Do you like spicy?
-Come on.
-Yeah?
Have these been toasted off?
-Yes.
-Garlic.
Salt and water.
♪♪
[ High-pitched voice ]
That's not hot at all.
We are making our
homemade corn tortillas.
Mash them, water.
[ Normal voice ]
You don't want them too wet,
you don't want them too dry.
When it doesn't stick
to your fingers, that's when --
-Then we're good to go. Okay.
-Yeah.
Small balls.
All right.
All right, so we cook them
on the plancha,
and you're making these
to order each time?
To order -- yeah.
Barbacoa's ready.
Ooh, yeah.
Gorgeous.
Break it up.
Very simple, very delicious.
Add a little bit of cilantro,
add onion, limes.
You want salsa?
-Come on.
-There you go.
-Do I want salsa?
So, a real
Chihuahua style, huh?
-Yeah.
-No lettuce and cheese?
No, none of that.
I love Mexico.
The Mexican culture
really celebrates life.
The appreciation for food
is so important.
-Yeah.
-And when I taste this,
I'm not just eating a great
taco, I'm tasting culture.
I'm tasting the hard work
of you and your husband.
♪♪
And getting that cheek meat,
it's got a nice fat,
it's very unctuous,
perfectly made tortilla,
just the right amount
of onion in the cilantro.
That's real deal --
congrats.
SERVER:
Tres taco de barbacoa.
The meat was just full of
rich flavors, very smoky.
FIERI:
And I knew the food must rock
when I got the recommendations
from two "Tripe D" alums --
Chef Silvana from Barrio Cafe,
and Bret Shapiro from
Paradise Valley Burger Company.
Let's talk about this place.
It's a funky old building.
They had to modify
an old fast-food sign
I mean, this is legit.
Absolutely.
I feel like people bury things
with the cheese,
with the sauce, whatever it is,
and this is just --
all you get is that amazing
flavor of the meat,
the deliciousness
of the tortilla.
Not sure if that's
a word, but...
"Deliciousness"
or "tortilla"?
-"Deliciousness."
-I'm gonna go with it is.
Okay, cool.
MAN: Everything's simple
and done right.
That's why it's great.
We got gorditas coming.
These gorditas are
a little pocket of happiness.
The meat just, like, kind of
falls apart really easily.
What is this gordita
we're going to make?
So, we're making
our deshebrada.
-Deshebrada?
-Shredded beef.
We're using brisket
and chuck roll.
All right.
Onions, garlic, bay leaves,
salt, cover it with foil
and put it
in the smoker overnight.
So, the meat's
done and shredded.
Well, that's good.
There's nice fat in that.
And now we're gonna
make the salsa.
-Correct.
-Okay.
We have the chile
Colorado that's dry,
steeped in the hot water.
Mm-hmm.
Oregano, two garlic cloves,
salt, and --
Comino?
Water, and we're gonna blend it.
All right, now what's up?
We're gonna add lard.
We're getting old-school
Mexican here.
Let it melt.
My mouth is starting
to drool.
[ Laughs ]
Right in there, hot.
I like the way you roll.
We're gonna add
our shredded meat.
The skin-boiled potatoes.
Oh, this is gonna be
phenomenal.
Eh. [ Laughs ]
Eh.
[ Spoon clatters ]
Show off.
[ Laughs ]
All right,
what do we do next?
We're gonna work
our gordita dough.
Okay, so flour.
Salt, baking powder.
Mix the dry ingredients
together a little bit.
And then we're gonna
start slowly putting
the shortening in...
-Okay.
-...add milk to our water...
Mmm, that's how I like it.
...add it slowly.
All right.
We ball it,
put it in the fridge --
how long do we need
to let it rest?
Overnight.
Let's make it happen.
Gorditas are ready.
Stuff it with a little bit
of refried beans.
The chile Colorado,
which I should eat by fistfuls.
And...ready.
♪♪
You know what, Nadia?
This wrecks the whole
gordita game.
-Good.
-No.
[ Muffled ]
Good's here.
This is outstanding.
[ Normal voice ] The gordita
has got such texture.
There's such great chew.
It's like a really
dynamite pizza skin.
And then you stuff it with
the brisket and the chuck,
the little bit of potato
in there that's nice and creamy,
the Colorado's just really
nice -- not too spicy.
Honestly,
it's the lard --
that silkiness of
the fat that you get.
I really want
50 of those to go.
I'm not kidding you.
I want to throw a party
just to have these there.
That's how good they are.
That's ridiculous.
WOMAN:
The gorditas are delicious.
The chili, the meat, the
stuffing's always just right.
FIERI:
My buddy Danny here's the guy
you want to know
if you want to go
to anything really cool.
Why is this place so good?
-Because it's one of a kind.
You feel like it's made for you.
Tres tacos de pollo.
This is really dynamite.
You guys deserve all that
you're getting,
and there's a lot to come.
-Thank you.
Let's do that again.
Fantastic.
That's what I'm looking for!
Up next...
Wow.
...a funky little spot
in Dallas...
That'll make a bulldog
bite his chain.
I knew one of those
was coming.
FIERI:
...smoking and stacking
all kinds of creations.
This has wrecked very duck
sandwich anybody will ever have.
♪♪
I have been to more barbecue
joints than most people --
More than you can
shake a stick at.
More than I can
shake a stick at!
In country
and out of country
I've seen it all, so today here
in East Dallas, Texas,
I brought my buddy,
barbecue guru
David Knight
from Ole Hickory Pits,
and tell me, how leg--
-Do I get to drive the car?
After we eat, David!
Are you hungry?
-Heck yeah!
This is One90 Smoked Meats.
MAN:
Chili mac coming.
This is the best
barbecue place of all.
MAN:
Three meat plate in the window.
I'm, like, crazy about it.
MAN:
Hot ham working.
These guys seem to have it
all nailed down.
FIERI:
That's 'cause Herman Guerra
and Kyle St. Clair
worked out the kinks
in their backyards
till they were ready
to quit their day jobs.
I worked for a Federal judge,
did a law clerkship.
And then you just thought you'd
trade that in for a smoker?
Yeah.
That smoke makes you crazy,
present company included.
MAN: Chopping brisket
for the Spicy Brisket.
I'm having the
Spicy Brisket sandwich.
MAN: You get a nice element
of the smoke,
you get the true flavor
of the actual brisket.
All right, so let's talk
about the brisket first.
ST. CLAIR: We don't pull
all the fat off.
Fat is where a lot of flavor is,
and so what we're gonna do
is just season our brisket
with salt and pepper.
Look at that.
It's a flick of
the wrist, David.
-Stunning.
-Squirt bottle with the pepper,
that gives it a nice,
even shot at it.
It definitely gets to
the perfume of it.
-In the smoker --
-Six hours.
We'll bring it out,
we'll wrap it,
and then we'll finish it,
4-6?
4-6.
We're gonna make our
Spicy Barbecue sauce.
-All right.
-Start with a little --
A little bit of the drip
from the brisket.
Tomato sauce,
do a little bit of ketchup.
Are you a ketchup
barbecue sauce guy?
There's so many different kinds.
Sometimes yes, sometimes no.
Okay.
No, I'm with you.
Vinegar, a little liquid smoke,
chipotle peppers,
onion powder, garlic salt.
Anything scaring you so far?
Not yet.
He's good.
He's watching you
with a close eye.
-I'm watching it.
-Creole mustard.
Got to have a little
mustard in there.
Now we're cooking.
Add some Worcestershire,
molasses.
Ooh, that's your sweet.
A little black pepper,
some honey.
Garlic.
Hey, sugar.
-Settle down.
-It's great.
I get to use all my
old material on David.
It's like new stuff.
Now, we're gonna let that cook
normally for about an hour.
-Good sauce.
-Let's get some brisket.
You don't even need
a knife with that.
You can cut that
with a bad look.
-That's beautiful.
-Give it a little pull test.
Don't tell me I didn't get you
anything nice for your birthday.
Mmm.
That would make
a bulldog bite his chain.
I knew one of those
was coming.
That's good pepper.
Nice unctuous fat --
just melts.
Now, do you serve sliced plates?
We serve it by the pound,
we serve it on plates --
On plates?
Well, you don't say.
What do you say we put
a sandwich together?
-Let's do it.
-Let's go.
So, we're gonna get
our roasted poblano pepper,
drop on our in-house
smoked cheddar cheese...
Now we're cooking.
...then we get our meat on,
the brioche bun...
The bun is beautiful.
-Yes, it is.
-...get a little sauce.
Get a little
of the red onion.
A full serving of pickle.
-There you go.
-Whoa.
Look at that.
-Mm-hmm.
-What do you think?
So, the barbecue, of course,
reigns supreme.
-Awesome.
-The brisket's not overcooked.
It's smoked the right amount,
good seasoning.
By itself, delicious.
But what you did
inside of the sandwich --
the poblano
and the pickles --
the acid, the onion,
smoked cheddar's dynamite.
You're really going
to the next level.
You these layer
after layer of flavor.
It's kind of like
a party going on.
You're coming to
the barbecue judge,
and you just made a real
good case for yourself.
It's true.
Brisket Sandwich.
It's lean and tender, rich
from the fat, not too fatty.
WOMAN: Poblano and the cheese
all mixed out together --
They make it delicious.
MAN:
Here comes your Philly, boy.
It's a small restaurant.
They have a small seating area.
It's mostly take-out.
We like to bring their meats
to cook for our cook-out.
You can grab a lot
of different options.
We've done bison,
we make salmon, ducks.
-Duck?
-Duck.
Gosh!
Talk to me about smoked duck.
We're gonna do a Duck
Lettuce Tomato sandwich.
We're gonna start with the
brine, the gallon of hot water,
some sugar, salt,
just a little bit
of pink salt...
Keeps that duck
from turning gray.
...bay leaves.
We're gonna add
a little thyme.
This is where you were
supposed to see the whisk,
and you're supposed to jump in.
That's your job.
Oh, that looks good.
[ Laughs ]
So, we get it dissolved.
We're gonna add some ice
to cool it down.
-How long we gonna brine that?
-Two days.
What do you want to do
for the next two days?
Do you like mini golf?
Uh...
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Hit it in the clown's mouth.
[ Laughter ]
Where does he get this stuff?
What's our next step?
A little bit of salt,
little bit of pepper,
and it goes right
in the smoker -- two hours.
So, when the duck comes out
of the smoker,
throw a little chill on it?
Yeah.
It helps with the slicing.
So, now we're gonna make
our cherry-chipotle sauce.
Start with a little cherry
juice, a little bit of sugar,
some chipotles,
fresh lime juice --
-And?
A little barbecue sauce.
That we made earlier.
And this is ready
once it starts to thicken.
Okay.
So, we're gonna
start with bread
from the local bakery,
butter on it.
Our duck's already cooked,
so we're just gonna
get it on and get off.
Pile our duck on...
KNIGHT:
That's a pile of duck.
...cherry sauce
that we just made,
a little tomato,
fresh lettuce,
top it off, slice it in half,
give it a try.
Okay.
Look at how nice
and thin that is.
♪♪
-Mmm.
-Wow.
Outstanding.
This has wrecked every duck
sandwich anybody will ever have.
The smoke is great,
the duck is tender,
the cherry sauce
plays in perfect.
Mmm.
-Mmm.
I thought
it was gonna be good --
This is fantastic.
The duck is super moist,
really, really flavorful.
It's delicious.
Last one, boys.
I have your salmon taco.
I'm a regular.
It just took one time,
and that was it.
I mean, you just got a real
contemporary mind
about the world of barbecue,
and I think it's refreshing.
It's real deal, man.
What do you think, boss?
You want to drive the car now?
You have to peddle fast.
Uh-huh.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
FIERI:
Coming up, a Longmont, Colorado,
joint all about beer and birds.
-It's a beautiful thing.
-That's good.
FIERI:
Dishing up the fried...
This is picnic chicken 101.
...plus a bit of a surprise.
That's indulgence right there.
You got some on your face there.
Right here?
-No...
-Right up there?
No, it's back there
on your mustache.
Did I get it?
You still --
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
I love coming to Colorado --
great weather, great people,
and so when I'm driving
through Longmont
right outside of Boulder,
and I see that there's
a fried chicken joint,
you know I got to check it out.
The bird is the word
a Post Chicken & Beer.
Four piece fried in the window.
I actually haven't had
chicken that good
since my grandma made it
when I was little.
Boom. Let's sell that
country gravy on there.
I won't go anywhere else now.
And I've had fried chicken
all around the country.
-Right.
-This'll set you free, brother.
This will set you free?
The liberator here is owner
Brett "Smitty" Smith,
whose simple Southern
concept is flying high
at the foot of the Rockies.
Beer and chicken.
Chicken and beer --
a match made in heaven, really.
It's a beautiful thing.
-That's good.
The chicken is crispy,
it's crunchy,
it's so moist on the inside.
They put it in
a pressure cooker.
Now that's a real-deal method
of cooking chicken
that I get nostalgic about.
First restaurant
I ever opened,
the restaurant before
was called Big John's Chicken.
-That had to be good.
-Oh, Big John was the best.
He's still great --
John Pavelko.
So when we took over,
he had three of these,
and I thought they were
the coolest things in the world.
It renders the fat better
inside of the chicken,
gives you a better skin.
-Just builds that crust up.
-So, let's get into this.
So the first thing we do
with our chicken --
we make a
lemon-and-rosemary brine.
Okay.
This is some
toasted coriander,
toasted black peppercorn,
crushed chili flakes,
a few bay leaves,
a slice of jalapeño,
a little salt --
a lot of salt, actually.
Brown sugar?
-Some apple cider vinegar...
-Okay.
...some good,
old Colorado water.
We add our fresh rosemary,
squeeze some lemon in there,
bring this up to a boil...
Let this simmer 20 minutes?
...strain it out.
So then we take that
and brine the chicken,
and how long are we gonna
brine the chicken?
Four hours.
All right.
Flouring's got to take place.
First part of that is we got to
make our house seasoning blend.
Okay.
So we got some chili powder,
some cayenne, toasted coriander,
onion powder, garlic powder,
black pepper, and salt.
Got it.
So then that goes into
our rice flour.
So we call this our
"First flour."
First flour.
So there's a lot of flour power.
A lot of flour power.
Yeah, a lot of hippies around.
[ Laughs ]
It gets coated in rice
flour overnight.
Soaks it up.
This starts to develop
that crust for us.
All right, so we got
that chicken that sat overnight
in the first flour.
-Got it, got it.
We're hitting it
with some buttermilk.
Okay.
So, now this second flour is our
top-secret, gluten-free blend.
"Top secret."
Top secret -- get this
coated up real good --
and then on these towers
we got the fatter part
of the breast on the outside,
then we do the two
thighs on the corners,
and this heating element
is around this way of the fryer.
That part's gonna cook
a little faster.
Okay.
And then the drumsticks
and the wings are the smallest,
so they get piled
in the middle.
-No kidding?
-Yep.
And then this gets put
in this rack like this.
-Wow.
-Yep.
We cook it 15 minutes
at 300 degrees,
and that builds up
the crust really nice.
And this thing just sounds
like it's ready to blow.
...Yep.
It's a chicken train
going to Flavortown.
Whoo-whoo!
This is how it comes out,
just like this.
Let it rest for a little bit --
bring this rack out...
Uh-huh.
...hit it with
our house seasoning...
in-house seasoning
that's in the flour.
Okay.
We're gonna plate this
with a breast, thigh,
a drumstick, and a wing.
-So you get half a chicken.
-You get half a bird.
♪♪
Wow.
This is picnic chicken 101.
Well, it's exactly
what you want it to be --
nice and tender,
not over seasoned.
The skin's nice
and crunchy.
In the library
at Flavortown,
this is one of the reference
pictures of fried chicken.
This is really dynamite.
SERVER:
Four piece fried in the window.
Very crispy, very tender,
very juicy.
Whatever they do
with the spices,
that blend is really good.
Best part about the chicken
is that it's gluten-free.
You can't find that anywhere.
We experimented countless ways
to cook the chicken.
We just did it that way
because that was the
best way it came out.
So it just happened to be that
gluten-free was the way to go.
-Exactly.
-And when it comes to the bird,
they're serving it up
every which way.
You roast chicken as well?
Roast chicken as well,
do a chicken and waffles,
we got wings.
Now you're starting
to brag a little bit.
-Yeah, well, I mean... Okay.
-You should.
-...you were pumping me up.
-Yeah. Well.
FIERI: And how about this bit
to boast about?
Some Chicken Chicharrones.
That's weird.
MAN: So, the Chicharrones
are chicken skin.
They fry it up real nice
and crispy for you,
and then they serve it
with this pinto bean hummus,
which is really, really good.
I like weird.
When we come back,
we're getting weird...
er -- weirder.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're in Longmont,
right outside of Boulder
at Post Chicken & Beer.
How do you get a name
that cool?
Serve chicken and beer?
That's how you do it!
Chicken and waffles
and a four banger.
MAN:
Being Colorado, you have to have
a good beer selection,
and they definitely have it.
FIERI: And you know what goes
great with beer.
-Chicken Chicharrones...
-O-kay.
...you don't see every day.
No. You don't.
I don't see actually at all.
MAN: Chicken Chicharrones
in the window.
It's a go-to appetizer.
The chicken skin's crisp
and fried to perfection.
Where'd you -- I mean,
I love the chicken skin.
Oh, yeah.
WOMAN: And the hummus is one of
the best hummuses
I've ever tasted.
It's got a lot of flavor in it.
-Chicken skins?
-Well, who doesn't
love the chicken --
-Everybody loves chicken skin.
It's the best part.
So, what do you got?
Give it to me.
We're gonna lay these raw
chicken skins
out on this tray...
-Okay.
...put these in the oven
at 350
for about 20 minutes?
And just -- really just
dry them out so when we fry them
they're gonna go snap,
crackle, pop.
-Exactly.
-And what do we serve this with?
We serve this with
a pinto bean hummus.
And that's what
I was thinking.
The first thing that came
to my mind is,
"Why not make a hummus
but out of pinto beans?"
Yeah.
So, we got some rinsed
pinto beans.
We call this our
"Garlic mojo."
It's roasted garlic with
scallion and fresh thyme...
Okay.
...and there's some
roasted poblano
get in that green chili,
get a little Colorado
flavors in there.
Salt and pepper, of course.
-Tahini.
-Yep.
Lemon juice.
And then we're gonna
start spinning this
and hit this
with some vegetable oil.
♪♪
That just screams,
"I want chicken skin."
-Let's fry some chicken.
-All right.
Fry them for about
five minutes,
get them nice and crispy
on both sides.
Got it.
We toss them in our house
seasoning,
a little bit of salt
or a lot of salt.
Give them a little spin.
Dude, this is --
You will not find this.
We got our hummus.
We get a little more
roasted poblano on top,
some more of our
garlic mojo on top.
That's the roasted garlic with
the fresh herbs and scallion.
Fresh carrots and celery,
and then we're just gonna
arrange our Chicharron...
Dude.
Load it up,
then you dip away.
♪♪
[ Crunches, snaps ]
[ Crunches ]
Uh-huh.
♪♪
That's everything
you want it to be --
light and crispy,
not very oily --
[ Chicken skin crunches ]
house seasoning's great,
chicken's got great crunch.
When you cut it with a little
bit of that pinto bean hummus,
that's indulgence right there.
[ Crunches ]
...the first time we've ever
had chicken skin Chicharrones
on "Triple D."
You can take the title,
my friend.
Gladly.
SERVER:
Chicken Chicharrones right here
with our homemade hummus.
Full-flavored, crispy,
great with the hummus.
[ Crunches ]
If it could be as decadent
as possible, it is.
MAN:
Okay, plate of roasted bird.
MAN #2: The food's wonderful,
the people are fantastic.
I love coming here.
When you fly into Denver,
this is worth jumping in the cab
and getting down here.
Thank you, man -- appreciate it.
Nice job, brother.
Great working with you.
Watch out for this gangster.
So, was this a great
road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
Listen to me --
The lens cap came off.
Listen when I tell you
something!