I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ha-ha!
...we're cruisin'
on a collision course...
You are
all over the place.
...crashing together
a fusion of flavor...
That is bananas.
Bananas is good.
...like an Asian-Latin
mash-up in Chicago...
Hey, you got your bánh mí
in my burrito.
...island comfort combos
in Hawaii...
Last thing
I expected to see.
...and a funky chicken joint...
[ Imitates
chicken clucking ]
...waking up Seattle
with some Nashville spice.
Whoo!
The sirens are going off
at the dam in Flavortown.
That's all right here right now
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, on "Triple D,"
what have we served up?
Well, we've served you a little
South American in North America.
We served a little Italian
in Texas.
We've served some tacos
in Nebraska.
You get the point, right?
So, it'd just be fitting
that we'd give you
a little Nashville in Seattle.
Call your mamas and papas,
'cause this is
Sisters and Brothers.
Those need about
10 more minutes.
Sisters and Brothers is known
for their Nashville chicken.
Got the dark meat with corn.
MAN:
If you love fried chicken,
this is definitely a place
not to sleep on.
They do things that nobody else
in Seattle is doing.
FIERI:
Because their owner, Jake Manny,
it's all about what he fell
in love with in Tennessee --
that spicy Nashville chicken,
served up
with down-home attitude.
I wanted to make a place
that felt comfortable
and, like, embraced.
FIERI:
Like you would be
if you're hanging out
with your sisters and brothers.
Yeah.
FIERI: And part
of their restaurant family...
Let's do it.
...is Chef Susie Tweedy,
who's lighting
this place on fire.
It's so spicy and delicious.
So what are
we making here?
We're gonna make
the house hot
that'll go in the brine
for the chicken.
So, we're not only
gonna make the chicken hot,
we're gonna make
the dredge hot?
Yep.
And we're gonna make
what goes on the dredge hot?
Yep.
That'll be nice.
We'll start with the water,
apple-cider vinegar.
It'll make it
a little bit sweeter.
Less deadly?
Yeah.
Okay.
Chile de árbol.
This is
the beginning of pain.
Yeah, exactly.
Kosher salt.
Just a pinch
of red-chili flake.
Just a little bit.
A little bit.
Whole garlic cloves,
and cayenne pepper.
Very diabolical.
Bring it to a boil.
Then you'll go with
the immersion blender?
Yeah. Strain it
and it'll be ready to go.
I'm just gonna stir it
and see if it'll take
my polish off my watch.
It might.
It's like a slow heat.
Nah, it's in there.
Oop, there it is.
Yep.
So this'll be the brine
for the chicken.
Start with whole milk,
some buttermilk,
and this is the house hot.
Chicken goes down
in the brine for how long?
24 hours.
And we'll make
the dry dredge.
Start with your flour.
A little bit of thyme.
Garlic powder,
a little bit of cayenne,
black pepper,
a smoked paprika...
Salt.
...onion powder
and Old Bay.
Mix that up.
You'll go straight from
the brine into the flour.
Yep.
Into the buttermilk?
Yes.
Back in bowl.
Back-back-back.
Somebody's been havin'
too much hot sauce.
Into the fryer.
What temperature?
350.
You want it
to, like, crisp...
Okay.
...and then,
move it down to 300.
The low and slow?
Yeah.
Okay, Chef,
what's up next?
The mild lard.
The mild lard?
Yeah.
We have the lard
that's liquefied.
Brown sugar.
Just a little bit of cayenne.
Just a touch.
Oop. Nope.
Ah. Kid. Uh...
Ohh.                        Ohh.
You should wear goggles
when you're making that.
That how
we're doing it now?
Work like this all day.
Garlic powder...
A little salt.
...and pepper.
Like the black pepper
really has a chance to survive.
It's just for fun.
You're just whimsical.
♪♪
And we're gonna just --
like you're painting a picture.
The sirens are going off
at the dam in Flavortown.
We're doing this
in true Nashville style.
We're getting white bread
and pickles.
Collard greens.
Come on.
♪♪
Nah, it's not hot.
Not juicy, either.
♪♪
Mmm.
Boy, that's good crunch on that.
Look at that.
♪♪
The heat,
the sweet, the vinegar...
That's legit,
right there.
Mmm.
That's a good hot.
Nicely done, Chef.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
♪♪
I've never had
chicken this good.
WOMAN:
The meat is very juicy
and it slides
right off the bone,
but the skin
is super crispy.
You made it to Nashville without
actually going to Nashville.
I have.
FIERI: And while Nashville hot's
pretty new in town,
this location's definitely not.
FIERI: How old's
this building?
110 years old.
Really?
It just looks 107.
It just, I mean...
♪♪
It's got, like,
a really cool, funky vibe.
You can bring your friends
without any pretense
and just enjoy a great meal.
FIERI:
Which goes beyond the burn.
Got mac and cheese
with bacon.
This is beyond
Grandma's-level mac and cheese.
'Cause Grandma didn't
smoke her own bacon.
It's really, really delicious.
What're we
gonna make next?
The cure
for the pork belly
for our
house-smoked bacon.
Hit it.
Brown sugar, salt.
That was like
a little Julia Child "salt."
[ As Julia Child ]
Just a little bit of salt.
Ha-ha!
[ Normal voice ]
Cinnamon, fennel seed,
paprika,
whole juniper berries,
garlic powder,
onion powder...
A little curing salt.
Get a nice coating.
And we're gonna let this go
for how long?
Seven days,
then we'll put it in the smoker.
With what kind of wood
for how long?
A mesquite...
Okay.
...for about
6 to 8 hours.
We're gonna cool it
and slice it up.
And it's ready
to fry.
We're gonna make
the base
for the smoked-Gouda
mac and cheese.
Butter,
then we'll add the flour.
Equal parts
of flour and fat.
Slowly add the milk.
Here,
let me help out.
Oh, thanks.
Like sisters and brothers.
Ah.
Just like that.
Add your smoked Gouda.
That's Gouda gold.
It's pretty Gouda.
That joke
was not Gouda.
[ Laughs ]
A little bit of salt,
little bit of pepper,
and you're good to go.
You Gouda that right.
Add our noodles
to the warm mac base,
and then
it's ready to serve.
Top it with
a little bit of paprika
and lots of bacon.
Nothing like mounting it
with a little fried swine.
♪♪
Yum-yum-yum-yum-yum-yum.
All right.
That is just ridiculous.
Noodles are perfectly cooked,
the cheese ratio --
it's not too heavy,
it's not too much,
but the real star
of the whole thing
is house-cured bacon.
That is bananas.
And bananas is good.
♪♪
Mac and cheese is up.
It is good.
It's ridiculous,
isn't it?
It's really good.
The pairing with the Gouda
and bacon -- it's quite superb.
Frito pie and corn.
WOMAN: It's a place I could
come in, feel comfortable,
and the food is always amazing.
Well-done.
You're a superstar.
Thanks.
Watch out for this one.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next, a saucy spot
in Chicago...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
...where Latin classics
plus Asian flair...
I like that.
I didn't see that coming.
FIERI: ...make for
a mind-boggling equation.
I'll eat that all day
long. Matter of fact,
I think I'm going to.
That's the heaviest spoon
I've ever felt.
Oh, my God.
♪♪
So I'm here in Chicago
with one of my favorite chefs,
Richard Blais.
You are gonna love
this place.
This chef's knockin' out fusion
like we haven't seen.
She's -- No, just go ahead
and stay in the car.
She's doing Asian and Latin
together, and I mean --
Stay in the car.
This is a "no parking."
I need you to watch the car.
This is Saucy Porka.
Guy, I don't know
how to drive stick.
♪♪
Saucy Porka sandwich.
WOMAN: There's a number
of fusion places,
but this one has
the best food combinations.
Cubana, chorizo egg roll.
Just the different spices
of both the Latin and the Asian
coming together is really good.
FIERI:
But it took a winding road
to get to this point
for Chef Amy Le.
I grew up
in the restaurant business.
Mom owned
Chinese restaurants,
went to school here
to become a journalist,
did that
for a while.
That's what most people do --
journalism, food.
And then, I was doing
an Asian sandwich truck,
bánh mís truck.
Okay, you met a buddy
that had a...?
He was doing
some Latin cooking.
Hey, you got your bánh mí
in my burrito.
[ Chuckles ]
Now with her own
brick and mortar,
she's taking that idea
and running with it.
I didn't want
to just have taco
and throw some kimchi
on it, right?
Right.
I really wanted
to have these flavors
and these spices kind of
really marry each other.
I wanted to make it authentic
and real and true.
And so,
we got our Asian paella.
The rice has
a lot of Spanish flavor,
and then they have Asian spices
that add a lot of complexity
to the dish.
She uses pork,
and it just complements
the flavors beautifully.
So what are we
gonna make first?
We're making the marinade
for the pork.
Let's see it.
Bucket of water,
green scallions, ginger,
a peppercorn blend...
Check.
...cloves,
some star anise, cinnamon.
We got
a whole lot of sugar.
BLAIS: That's how you know
a recipe is authentic,
when it's just like a handful
of this, something of that.
A tub and a lotta.
Oyster sauce to make it
nice and salty, there.
Mushroom soy, mirin,
your soy sauce.
That would be a lotta.
Hey, no joke, I want
to take a bath in that.
It would help.
Why do you think
the car top was down?
And this is ready
for the pork.
Dried mushrooms
and bay leaves,
spread it evenly
throughout the pan.
Let it marinate
how long?
Overnight,
and stick in that oven
350 for 3 hours.
Got it.
Now we're gonna do the sofrito
for the paella rice.
Okay, so --
Queso?
There's gonna be cheese
in this?
Ooh.
Oh, I like that.
I didn't
see that coming.
Queso?
"Okay, so,
I'm about to make the sofrito."
Oh!
"Okay, so,
I'm about to make the sofrito."
Oh, okay. All right, so we're
gonna start with cilantro.
Which is big in both
Asian and Mexican food.
That's the bridge
between the cuisines.
Chef Blais is really excited
about the cilantro.
I'm really excited. There's so
much umami in this dish.
A little garlic,
get some oil in there,
got some salt,
chopped onions.
This is my favorite part
of "Triple D," by the way.
When a bunch of really awesome
things get blended together.
I'm just --
You are so excited.
You've got to cut down
on caffeine.
All right.
Let's make this rice.
Some vegetable oil, then we're
gonna drop the sofrito in here,
coconut milk...
Chicken base?
Yeah, some salt here,
Sazón...
Have you used Sazón?
I do.
It's a little
Latino seasoning.
So we use
the saffron one.
Okay.
And 2 cups of water.
Jasmine rice.
This is gonna cook
about 25 minutes.
Now we're gonna build
the fried rice?
We got some vegetable oil,
green scallions,
mild pork sausage...
Okay.
...Chinese sweet sausage,
add umami beans.
This is that paella rice that
we cooked in the coconut milk,
with the sofrito.
Add chili garlic.
Is that
a normal portion,
or just because Chef Blais
has on stretchy pants?
Yeah.
We actually --
We do really big portions here.
The pork carnita
straight out of the oven.
And we are going to top it
with some green scallions.
That's our Asian-style paella
there for you.
It's pae-yeah!
Fantastic.
Blais. Oop.
Um, oh, I'm sorry.
That doesn't make
anybody feel welcome.
Here's a stick.
Here's the other one.
I figured it out.
Oh.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Jump in
with your little sticks.
So the rice
is cooked perfectly.
The Chinese sweet sausage
really does play through,
and the sambal
gives it
a nice little sweet
and a little heat.
I loved how you have
the duality of texture in here,
you have these little
crispy bits of the sausage
mixed in with all this luscious
glazed pork.
Luscious?
Luscious.
And "duality."
This is "Triple D," bud.
Yes.
[ Laughter ]
I wanted it to have
the Asian influence,
the Mexican influence.
I wanted them
to come together harmoniously.
What I think
has really happened...
is exactly that.
I usually
disagree with Guy,
but in this case,
I totally agree with him.
This is a home run.
It really is
a fantastic dish.
MAN:
Asian-style paella.
WOMAN: It's a good combination
of sweet and savory,
with the pork carnitas.
You can't go wrong
with pork carnitas.
WOMAN #2: We would do
a lot of street food,
growing up in Vietnam,
and the sausage --
that's what it reminds me of.
It's so good.
I got three pork tacos here.
Chef Amy is a great cook.
Her food is unique
from everywhere else
you're gonna find down here.
Where are we?
All I know is that we were
in a no-parking zone --
well, somebody was in
a no-parking zone.
We are in the heart
of the financial district.
So, lunch is,
uh, ridiculous.
Dinner time's a nice time
to come visit?
No dinner here.
I like to hang out
at home with my family.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're talking to
restaurant vets, right here.
There's no such thing
as not being open for dinner.
Especially after
this airs.
Oh, yeah, by the way.
Yeah.
Lunch will now
go to 7:00.
LE:
Shrimp tacos here.
MAN:
The business people here --
they're diving into
a new experience
of spices
and traditional foods together.
Chef Blais and I hanging out
in Chicago at Saucy Porka.
I got to check on the car 'cause
I don't know where he parked it.
You got anything else
you want to make us?
Uh --
Don't tell me now.
FIERI:
But here's a hint.
It's comfort city, baby.
Pork pozole.
The pozole soup is delicious.
It's just a really filling,
satisfying dish.
See you in a minute.
All right, everyone,
welcome back to "Triple B."
That's right, it's
"Blais, Brasseries, and Bars."
Chef, what do we got
working here?
We're gonna do
some pozole.
Ho, ho! Hey, hey.
Nice try.
See?
You go to one little commercial
and your buddy
just slides right in.
FIERI:
That'd be Chef Richard Blais,
who's hanging out with me
at Saucy Porka in Chicago,
where Chef Amy Le's all about
mixin' Latin and Asian flavors.
Cubana comin' up.
The food's amazing.
I can always find something
that's gonna hit the spot,
whether it's the shrimp tacos
or warm soup on a cold day.
Pozole.
Pozole is
one of my favorite dishes.
You have the Asian slaw
that has the crunch,
and the pork carnitas
that are super tender.
It will warm you inside,
all the rest of your day.
What's the game plan?
We're gonna get
some pozole cooked up.
Make it happen,
Captain.
Nice.
We're gonna drop pork bone,
garlic cloves, onions,
some tomatilloes
and some tomatoes
that we have grilled up.
All right.
Water,
pasilla peppers.
Pasilla peppers?
Guajillo,
Japanese red,
we add chile de árbol,
oregano...
Boy, you are
all over the place.
...coriander, cumin,
tri-color peppercorn,
salt here,
chicken base.
Whoo-ooh!
So this steeps
for about 30 minutes.
Blend it
and then strain it.
Yes.
Chef,
let's see it.
We're gonna put some hominy
in the bowl, here.
How many hominy
is that?
[ Chuckles ]
And that delicious pork
that we cooked earlier today,
some of the cabbage here,
pour some of this broth,
fresh cilantro,
green onions,
tortilla chips to add
some crispiness to the soup.
There you go.
All right, Blais,
I'm gonna try
this first,
and then
you get sloppy seconds.
[ Chuckles ]
You know that you've got to be
really good friends
when you're sharing
a bowl of soup together.
That's true. Unless we put,
like, a soft egg on top of it.
Get away from me.
[ Laughs ]
That's really tasty.
I'm gonna have to say it.
The flavors are
in perfect hominy.
My question is,
hominy times do people come in
and order this
twice in a day?
♪♪
It does have
a funk
that's beyond
traditional Latin pozole.
A little bit of cabbage
in there,
the cilantro
and the onion.
I do believe it's
some of the pork in this adobo
that's really kind of adding
the extra piece to it.
Do you agree?
Yeah, that's where
you're getting all those
Asian flavors,
from all of the mirin
and the marinade
and the oyster sauce
that the pork
is cooked in.
Exactly.
That's what really makes this
a great fusion dish.
Scratch-made, creatively made.
Delicious.
I'm glad
you're enjoying it.
Pozole up in the window.
It's like a party in my mouth.
I love it. It's so good.
MAN: The pork is tender,
the hominy adds great texture.
It's better than my grandma's.
Your shrimp special.
WOMAN: They stay true
to the flavors.
Everything meshes really well.
Can't ask for more.
MAN #2: I don't know
what she's doing back there,
but whatever she does,
it's fantastic.
And that fusion line, you're
threading it really finely,
and it's coming out.
It's delicious.
I'd eat that all day
long. Matter of fact,
I think I'm going to.
Nice having you,
Blais.
You did a great job.
You're not sharing anymore?
Goodbye.
FIERI: Comin' up,
on the Big Island of Hawaii...
I'm impressed.
...mainland mainstays...
You talk about
melt-in-your-mouth barbecue.
...topped with a tropical twist.
The only thing
that this should come with
is a free hour
of outrigger classes...
Right.
...because you're
gonna need it after that.
♪♪
So, when you find yourself
on the Big Island of Hawaii,
most likely,
you're gonna come to Kona.
And if you come to Kona,
you're gonna end up here
on Ali'i Drive.
That takes you from
downtown Old Kona to New Kona.
And what are you looking for?
Let's say you're looking
for a breakfast, lunch,
and dinner joint
that's got a mainland feel
but with a Big Island twist.
It's right here
at Island Lava Java.
♪♪
Risotto with Kauai shrimp
in the window.
Lava Java is the place.
MAN: Stuffed pork chop
be done in two minutes.
It's been around
for quite some time.
FIERI: Since '92, to be exact,
when it was just a coffee house.
How are you today?
Owner Jeff Fischer bought it,
moved it, expanded it, and hired
Vegas native Josh Ratigan
to run their
island-mainland mash-up.
Two burgers, how long?
MAN:
2 1/2 minutes, Chef.
WOMAN:
A lot of mainlanders come here,
and they're still looking
for their comfort food.
But you give them
a little bit of the twist
of what the island food
can taste like.
MAN:
Guava ribs in the window.
Where do you get ribs
with guava sauce?
You're not gonna find this
on the mainland.
So let's get into it.
We're gonna season
our ribs,
take our smoked salt.
Love this smoked salt.
Yep.
Black pepper.
We just put them
in our vacuum-seal bags.
Okay.
2 garlic cloves and a couple
sprigs of fresh rosemary.
Vacuum-seal this?
Yep.
An immersion circulator --
last thing I expected to see.
I'm impressed.
We're gonna go at 157
for 18 hours.
18 hours?!
Yes.
You got sunrises
and sunsets,
and you're missing
all that.
That's that kitchen life.
You know.
Yeah.
They come out,
you let them cool.
And then we finish them
on the grill.
You're a real gangsta.
Oh, yeah.
Been in kitchens
since I was 8 years old.
Next step?
Okay, so we're gonna make
our guava barbecue sauce.
We have oil, and we're gonna
take our ginger...
Okay.
...garlic...
Onions.
Your smoked salt.
Of course.
And black pepper.
And we're gonna deglaze
with red-wine vinegar,
Worcestershire.
We're gonna
add our brown sugar,
our Dijon mustard,
then our lilikoi.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay.
Passion fruit.
[ Laughs ]
Don't try to act
like you're local.
And then we got to have
our ketchup.
Gonna finish with
our guava concentrate.
Let it reduce down.
Take our stick
immersion blender, finish it,
and then we're gonna
strain it through a chinois.
To make sure
that the sauce is super fine.
Last finishing touch?
Tropical salsa.
So we have chopped papaya
from the island,
red onion,
our fresh pineapple,
some cilantro,
green onions,
lime juice, salt,
a little bit of cayenne pepper.
And mix that up.
Bananas?
No.
There's no banana in there.
But it is really good.
So we got the ribs
on the grill,
we basted them, let them get
nice and caramelized,
and then we finish
with the tropical salsa
and some fresh chives
right over the top.
♪♪
You talk about
melt-in-your-mouth barbecue.
This has been treated
with such tender love and care.
By putting it in
the immersion circulator,
you are basting it
in its own fat
for a ridiculous amount
of time.
But the rib
melts in your mouth.
The rosemary hint
is outstanding,
along with the sweet side
of the salsa
and the guava barbecue sauce
just play incredibly well.
When you talk about
putting that island flair,
it's a cross between a really
good rib and kalua pork.
That's pulled pork
on the bone.
Dynamite.
MAN:
The guava barbecue ribs.
Everybody loves to come here
for those ribs.
They're so tender and flavorful.
It's fun to come down here.
It's breakfast, lunch, dinner.
The atmosphere is unbeatable.
When you're in Hawaii,
that's what you want --
ocean view and great food.
You can find something
for any appetite.
The Big Island pizza.
WOMAN: This pizza is
the real Hawaiian pizza.
It's got kalua pork,
pineapple, cheese.
Big Island pizza?
I don't know,
how'd you come up with the name?
We're on the Big Island.
And what else?
Ah.
You know
what I'm saying?
Talk to me
about making dough.
We start off
with the flour.
High-gluten flour.
Rosemary.
In the pizza dough?
Yes, sir.
Did you get hit
with a surf board, or...?
Yeah. Some granulated garlic,
sugar, salt...
Got it.
...yeast,
and then our basil.
And then
we add ice water.
How long are we
gonna let this go?
About 20, 25 minutes,
until it balls up.
Let it proof, portion it,
let it proof again.
Yep.
Going 24 hours.
Exactly.
All right, Chef,
kalua pork.
So we have our pork butt here.
We're just gonna score it first.
We have our ti leaves
right in here.
Gonna take
our smoked salt.
Love this smoked salt.
Water,
some more ti leaves.
More parchment.
Yep.
Plastic and then foil.
In the oven how long?
Seven hours.
So the dough's done.
We're gonna hit it with
some mozzarella cheese first.
The pulled pork done
in the ti leaves.
Pulled pork, yep.
Shred it.
And then, we're just gonna
finish with some of our...
Local pineapple.
Go into the oven
for about five to six minutes.
And the sauce for this
is sweet chili?
Yep.
Right on the plate.
♪♪
The chili sauce -- it's not as
sweet as I thought it would be.
The dough --
very interesting.
Rosemary, basil.
So,
it's a cross between...
conventional pizza
and, like, a flatbread.
Right.
I dig
that you're making it yourself.
The only thing
that this should come with
is a free hour
of outrigger classes...
Right.
...because you're gonna
need it after that.
Well-done, Chef.
Thanks.
Up in the window,
Big Island pizza.
It's really terrific.
The flavors come together
just beautifully.
The roasted-veggie pizza.
Come to Lava Java. It's
definitely the best in Kona.
It's just a great place
to come in and have a nice time.
You got a lot going for you.
People are lucky to have you.
Well-done.
You're a pro.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Okay,
so we're gonna make
our guava barbecue sauce
for our guava barbecue --
Did you just try
to hold my hand?
I tried,
but I missed.
[ Laughs ]