Hey, there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Start this party.
We're grabbing a
bite of barbecue...
I can't shovel it in
fast enough, bro.
...and diving into
Southern flavors.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
That means hearty home style
in North Carolina...
That's the kind of dish
you'd fall asleep in.
...chicken and fixings
in Oakland...
I'm taking it all to go.
...plus killer 'cue
in Seattle...
That's the money spot
right there.
...smoked up in
a belly of a beast.
This is a feat of
engineering madness.
That's all right here,
right now.
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
I'm here in the Central District
of Seattle, Washington,
to check out a barbecue joint.
And listen before
you say anything,
I know, you say what kind
of barbecue joint is it?
I mean how legit,
what kind of smoke,
what kind of smoker,
what is their style?
I said listen, it's
all gonna be proven,
'cause I hear they're running
a 1,000-gallon smoker.
This is Wood Shop BBQ.
♪♪
Working on the Woody right now.
What a food explosion.
DAVIS: Half rack of ribs
and potato salad.
It's outstanding.
Legit.
This is the best barbecue,
you're gonna get.
Excellent.
What makes it so outstanding
is Matt Davis.
He's a Kansas kid that's lived
in Seattle for a long time.
FIERI: And along with his buddy,
James Barrington,
Matt set out to bring the
Midwest to the Northwest
after trading a career in
wood sales for a giant smoker.
DAVIS: This is Big Willie.
Whoa.
Is this like a space
shuttle fuel tank?
No, it's an old thousand-gallon
propane tank.
We basically just cut it up.
Okay, this is a feat of
engineering madness.
Where'd you learn to smoke?
Figured it out.
Like, I literally
was just homesick.
In Central Kansas, that's,
like, you have P.E., math.
Ribs.
Yeah, and ribs.
We've got the ribs
and the mac.
This is the place you got to go
if you want to get good ribs.
The rub is just amazing.
FIERI: And custom made.
We call it saw dust, it's
more of a Kansas City rep.
Saw dust, wood shop,
I get it.
So, we've got granulated garlic,
granulated onion,
cayenne powder, chili powder.
We've got paprika,
brown sugar, black pepper.
Coarse grind, okay.
Then we've got kosher salt.
All right, I see some ribs.
And this is
a St. Louis cut.
It means they clean it up
to make it a little bit
more uniform.
Are you gonna peel
the silver skin?
That membrane on the inside.
I usually just score it.
I've started to leave it on.
It holds the rib together
better when it's more tender.
All right, this goes on
in this 375 degree smoker.
Once it gets that good,
dark mahogany color,
after about two and a half
to three hours,
add a little bit of spritz
of apple juice into it,
and just a touch of sauce.
Okay.
Then we put it back on for
about an hour and a half.
It's about a five,
five and a half hour rib.
Oh, this I got to try.
Now we're into
barbecue sauce.
Start off with ketchup,
yellow mustard,
apple cider vinegar,
Worcestershire sauce.
Washersister sauce.
[Worcestershire]
Molasses, kind of a
deep, darker sweet.
Louisiana hot sauce,
chili powder,
cayenne pepper,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion,
brown sugar, kosher salt,
black pepper,
and then from there,
let it simmer about an hour.
Foil capital
of the world here.
Taste this, Guy.
What a nice looking rib.
Juicy, nice bark.
That's a normal order
right there?
Yeah, that's a
half rack of ribs.
Really good smoke, got a
nice big smoke ring in there.
Wow. When you get
a lot of folks
that are coming
from the Midwest,
are they preferring
the bread?
The Midwest purists
definitely appreciate it.
It's like an edible
napkin, right?
Mm-hmm. Delicious.
Sauce is fantastic.
Well done.
SERVER: Ribs and beans.
It falls off the bone,
but it doesn't fall apart.
That's key.
Taste the smoke,
you can taste the wood.
Especially the hickory wood that
he trucks in here from Kansas.
FIERI: Which he's mixing
with post oak from Texas.
You're stick burning
this whole thing,
you are consistently
running this with
the fluctuating
temperature of Seattle.
And no gauges.
Really?
They have mastered it.
Three briskets all day.
Any BBQ place I go to, I always
judge it by the brisket.
And this brisket
is just amazing.
So, we're gonna do
brisket next.
Get rid of the deckle,
the big hard fats.
Then there's also some real
silky fat surrounding it.
Right.
I want to keep that fat.
So now, just gonna
dry rub this?
It's a coarse ground
black pepper, kosher salt.
Lay it on heavy.
How long is this gonna
go in the smoker for?
11 to 12 hours.
So, after about 9 hours,
you pull the briskets off,
spritz them with apple juice.
Wrap them in butcher paper,
then put them back
on the smoker until they
reach around 205 degrees.
Look at that.
I'd just like to be in
the recycling department
of your team.
Look at the bark
on that, huh?
That's the money spot
right there.
Mmm, see all that
juice coming out?
Delicious.
Each bite is like an extra 10
minutes on the treadmill.
Hi, elliptical.
My name's Guy.
[ Chuckles ]
The bark on here is what
defines good brisket.
It's not too fatty, but you
can still cut it with a spoon.
It's like meat candy.
FIERI: Served up from platter
to bun to bowl.
SERVER: Brisket chili.
Brisket chili is something
that'll warm your heart.
It's really good.
And we're gonna make what?
Texas style chili
with no beans.
We use our left-over brisket.
So, we start off with
olive oil, diced onions,
chopped garlic, tomato sauce,
chicken stock,
beef broth...
Cumino.
Cumin, brown sugar,
molasses.
How impressed is your
mom and dad with your
newfound love of cooking?
As barbecue fans, they're
extremely happy with me.
What's your pop's name?
Bud.
Bud, come on down,
I think there should be
a little barbecue cook-off
between you and the kid.
Bet my money on Bud.
[ Laughs ]
So we drop in our
guajillo chilies,
These are New Mexico chilies,
and we let those go for
a little while to kind of
reanimate them
and stuff like that.
Reanimate them?
Is reanimate a word?
I'm 90% full of it.
90%.
[ Laughs ]
I thought you were gonna say,
"I'm 90% sure
reanimate's a real word."
We add a dark chili powder,
light chili powder,
then we add cayenne pepper.
That's a lot of heat.
Then we're gonna
make it even hotter
to do our Louisiana
hot sauce.
This thing just turned
into pepper, after pepper,
after pepper.
And then black pepper,
green chilies.
Chipotles in adobo sauce.
That adds that extra
little smoky flavor.
Diced tomatoes now, and
we're gonna let it cook.
Then we're gonna hit it
with an immersion blender.
Left over brisket,
we chop it up.
How long is this
gonna cook down for?
For about an hour.
And then how are we
gonna serve it up?
We put this on
our mac and cheese,
and we also do a chili pie.
That's my middle name.
Create our base,
nice helping of chili,
This the whole family
Thanksgiving platter.
Cheddar cheese, and a
little bit of sour cream.
That's ridiculous.
In my opinion,
this is competition chili.
I mean, this is legit.
Got a lot of balance
with the heat.
The whole thing that
brings it together
that makes me the
happiest about it,
is the meatiness
of the brisket.
Really good texture.
Yeah, I can't shovel it
in fast enough, bro.
Blew my socks off.
Like the perfect comfort food.
You need to have this,
like, once a day.
This is a good one.
Once a day.
How good, 1 to 10?
11.
I like the way you count.
They're killing it.
From a wood salesman,
to a big, gigantic
1,000-gallon propane tank,
sure have done well.
It's been a blast.
Congrats.
Up next, in Wilmington,
North Carolina...
That's "A" game all day long.
...a joint not messing around
when it comes
to building up breakfast...
Gravy, bacon, chicken,
cheese, biscuit meal?
...or cooking up a classic.
This is when the meatloaf's
bigger than your head.
So, I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina,
in the Porter's Neck area,
about a mile and a half
from the beach.
Now, you won't remember that.
What you will remember is
that there's this
little mom-and-pop joint,
where they're serving up some
North Carolina favorites
with their own
funky little twist.
This is the Cast Iron Kitchen.
All right boys, here we go.
♪♪
Gravy and grits up.
A little bit of classic
Southern, but a new style twist.
PETTY: Got another dirty
going to the window.
WOMAN: It's things that you've
probably had before,
but you haven't had all
those components together.
FIERI: And it's all put
together by Josh Petty.
He owns this down-home spot
with his family
who helps out
at the restaurant...
Good morning.
...and with the inspiration.
It's food that I learned from
my grandmother's and my mom.
You were born
and raised here?
Yes.
So, the whole premise was,
make North Carolina shine.
Use the purveyors,
the farmers.
And that local flavor stands out
in this pumped-up classic.
The Dirty South Biscuit.
The sausage gravy
just reeled me in.
Add the bacon, the chicken,
it's perfect.
Tell me about biscuits
in North Carolina.
I mean, I think
that's what you get
judged by in life,
isn't it?
Like, can you make a
good biscuit or not.
We like to use
really good buttermilk.
Flour mixed with baking powder,
some butter flakes.
We try to put a little bit
more shortening in ours
to make them a little bit
more tender.
'Cause you're not
necessarily the doctor?
Right, I'm the chef.
Powdered sugar
and baking powder.
Together again for
the first time.
Little iodized salt,
work that by hand
until we get the dough
to the proper consistency.
Okay.
Roll them out next.
You don't want
to overwork it,
and if there's some
cracks, that's okay.
No one said it had to
be a pretty biscuit.
Throw them in
a 335 degree oven.
Not 340?
Not 340, 335,
for about 18 minutes.
Now we're gonna make
our country sausage.
Let's start this party.
Lot of kosher salt,
red pepper flake,
onion powder, dried sage.
Sage and sausage.
Isn't that a band?
Sage and sausage?
It should be.
Coarse black pepper,
fresh sage, white pepper.
And then the kitchen sink.
Fresh rosemary and thyme.
The country sausage's done.
We're making the gravy.
Got a little oil blend.
What was that again?
Ole.
That's how they say
it in the South.
Whole butter, onions, chorizo,
our country sausage mix.
[ Whistles ]
Hit it with cayenne,
sage, heavy cream.
And then we're gonna add
our thickening agent,
some culinary cream.
It's got
some emulsifier in it.
Whole milk.
They also own
the gym next door.
I have a man cave in there
for them too, to relax.
There you go,
just keep it going.
Get a bar next to it,
then a B&B.
We're gonna let it simmer,
and then we're
gonna add some green onion,
black pepper,
kosher salt, dried sage.
Did we think about putting
any sage in this dish?
I've got a lot of sage.
Sage advice.
We're gonna let it simmer
for about 30 minutes.
Next up, fried chicken.
We're gonna go with
some North Carolina
buttermilk, hot sauce,
and then salt and pepper.
Whisk that up, then we
put our chicken in there.
That goes for a day.
Now what are we gonna
bread this in?
AP flour,
coarse ground pepper,
white pepper, salt, and
a little garlic powder.
And what kind of oil
are you running?
Canola.
After it's fried,
we're gonna put a piece of
pepper jack and Muenster cheese,
and put it in the broiler
for about 30 seconds.
Where's that cheese from?
Is that from Herman?
Herman Munster.
[ Laughs ]
Here's our homemade biscuit
with applewood smoked bacon.
Most people want to
have an egg right now,
but those of us that don't,
they just get to have
an extra scoop of gravy?
Yup.
If you want to use
your hands, you can.
No, people don't
really pick it up.
I've seen a few.
I can't say I'm that much
of a biscuit aficionado,
but this is nice, light, and
fluffy, nice crust on top.
Here we go.
So, the gravy's not
really big and heavy.
It's a lot lighter than
I thought it would be.
When you come
to North Carolina
and you think that
you're gonna have
a gravy, bacon, chicken,
cheese, biscuit, meal...
that's the kind of dish
you fall asleep in.
That's right.
♪♪
Dirty South up to the window.
Let's get it.
Just all the different things
he puts in there,
it's just so good.
WOMAN: To have it all in one
sandwich with fried chicken,
I don't think it gets
much dirtier than that.
We got a chicken and waffles.
Cast Iron Kitchen is
our favorite restaurant.
If they were open for dinner
we would be here every night.
We're just open
breakfast and lunch.
You can get a burger,
you can shrimp and grits,
soft shell crab, eggs benedict.
Favorite thing on the menu.
Meatloaf sandwich.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Not Your Mamas Meatloaf.
MAN: It's not your
traditional meatloaf,
and that's a good thing.
Mama's meatloaf?
Not My Mamas Meatloaf.
Okay, 'cause I just
talked to your mom
and she said this
ain't her meatloaf.
This isn't.
[ Laughs ]
We have a local
buttermilk again,
Worcestershire,
whole eggs, ketchup,
Sweated mirepoix so you
don't have raw veggies
inside of the meatloaf.
Panko, rosemary,
parsley, garlic powder.
Salt and pepper?
Salt and pepper.
We're gonna add
our ground pork,
and then our ground chuck.
All right, so you
put it in the pan,
holds all of its juices.
We're gonna put it
a 350 degree oven
for about an hour 15,
hour and 20 minutes.
So we've got the meatloaf
seared, we got some...
Holy moly.
...caramelized sweet onions,
little cheddar cheese.
We'll put the
trusty dome on top.
Little domey for my homey.
Little water, let it
get all nice and cozy.
Two slices of tomato,
herb aioli.
We're gonna take
it to the plate,
then a little hollandaise.
Then we're gonna
top that off.
This is your head.
This is when the meatloaf's
bigger than your head.
Been a while since I've jumped
into a big one like this.
This is outstanding.
Great moisture inside of it.
Right amount of ingredients,
really good meat,
great texture to the grind.
You made the herb aioli,
you've got the hollandaise
in there with
a little bit of spice.
That's "A" game all day long.
Thank you, Chef.
SERVER: Not My Mamas Meatloaf.
You have the nice texture,
with the crispy on the outside,
the tender, moist, and
delicious on the inside.
Feel like I died
and went to heaven.
It's real deal.
Excellent.
Good job, boys.
It's like Josh is back there
sprinkling magic dust
on everything.
There's a tremendous heartbeat
inside of this place.
It's the real deal.
Well done.
Thank you, Chef.
Be his friend only if
he gives you a treadmill.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up, Southern soul
in California...
"You got to eat it
to believe it."
...at a funky
Oakland joint...
Come on now.
...staying old school
and totally legit.
It's gonna get
dangerous right now.
It's about to go down.
I'll be running out the door
is what will be happening.
♪♪
I hope this is the right place.
I'm in Oakland,
that's MacArthur Boulevard,
people are eating fried chicken,
there's some ox tail.
Excuse me sir,
is this Southern Cafe?
Yes, it absolutely is.
You are in the right place.
That's what I'm looking for.
Welcome to Southern Cafe.
♪♪
Cafe's Dinner up.
I've been to the South,
and this is just as good
or even better.
I have turkey wings.
You're gonna get me in
trouble for saying this,
but it's way better than
my mom's and granny's.
FIERI:
Probably because Dede Carter
and her four siblings
learned from their mom, Esther,
who brought her native
Louisiana cooking to Oakland
when she opened her own
Southern spot in the late '60s.
She never hired anyone
to work in the restaurant
because she had her dishwasher,
she had her servers,
she made us great cooks.
And you're the chef
of this whole program.
Yes. One of them.
My sister Maralena,
we call her Big Mama.
This is her kitchen.
Big Mama's the boss?
Big Mama's the boss
of me, yes, she is.
Two minutes on
the liver and onions.
I love Dede and Maralena.
They cook very well.
They've been doing it for
a long time, you can tell.
Macaroni and cheese.
MAN: The mac and cheese
is excellent.
There's a blending
of cheese that
really brings it out,
so flavorful.
It almost melts in your
mouth as you're eating it.
So what are
we gonna make today?
We're gonna do
mac and cheese.
It's simple, we have the
simplest mac and cheese recipe.
Yeah, give me the lowdown
on the showdown
before I eat all the cheese.
I been noticing you
came in a little hungry.
Well our pasta, we add a
little salt, cayenne pepper.
I'm gonna add some of my
cheese if I have some left.
If there's any left.
Yeah.
Someone was picking,
a little mouse was at it.
Add my butter in.
That's a pound of butter.
That's it, yeah,
that's the trick.
I'm gonna add my eggs
to the milk and cream.
Pour it like this, Guy.
Watch me do it.
I'm gonna throw it
in the oven,
and it goes about
45 minutes to bake.
What are we gonna
serve this with?
Fried chicken.
SERVER: Fried chicken.
The chicken is crispy,
seasoned very well.
Perfect.
Fried chicken is one
of my favorite things.
It doesn't look like
I eat it very often.
Anyway.
Okay.
So, let's start
with the seasoning.
Salt, black pepper,
cayenne pepper.
Give me the dredge order.
Now is the flour seasoned?
We don't.
I won't lie to you Guy.
Sometimes at home,
I do season my flour.
You got to always
season your flour.
Seasoning is like this,
it's like layers.
Do me a favor.
Can you tell Big Mama?
Oh, I'm not
going to tell her.
I've been trying to get
Big Mama to do that, right?
You'll get me in trouble.
Don't tell her
we did that, okay?
Everything's good.
[ Whispers ]
She's right there.
Why do I feel like I'm 15
and I've just snuck
something out the back door?
[ Normal voice ]
Back to regular voices.
As we heavily season
our chicken,
we're gonna put it
in egg batter.
To the flour.
After we do that, it goes
to the fryer for 20 minutes.
20 minutes.
First, we start
with rice and gravy,
or mac and cheese for Guy?
Come on, big guy.
Oh, and I love
the corner part.
Oh, man.
Black-eyed peas.
Oh, I love black-eyed peas.
That's your chicken breast,
your thigh, and your leg.
Holy moly.
Those are really
dynamite black-eyed peas.
Mmm.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
♪♪
So, you know sometimes,
you go to a place
and get mac and cheese,
it's soupy.
Then you get a mac and
cheese, and it's dry.
And that's not the problem.
I see, I see.
That's legit mac and cheese.
I want to taste some
with you.
Get right after that.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm?
I'm good?
Yeah.
That's gonna be hot, Guy.
That's hot.
Going in the egg wash
really gives
that nice crumble
and crust to it.
Chicken is juicy.
It's super tender but it's
not falling off the bone.
It hasn't been overcooked.
It's not dried out.
That's a fried chicken dish,
and everybody thinks they got to
go to the Oakland terminal,
fly to Mississippi.
They don't need to even
buy a plane ticket.
They just come right
down the street.
You really like it.
Like it?
I love it.
I'm taking it all to go.
Three piece chicken.
The fried chicken here
is delicious.
It's very moist and tender.
Best mac and cheese ever.
MAN: They grew up underneath
their mother,
learning how to cook this food.
They hit on a tradition,
and they've done a great job.
Every time I've been here,
they come out and they speak.
They're nice people.
What hair colors
do you run,
'cause I think that
this magenta, it is hot.
You named it.
You know hair color.
Come on now,
this hair is awesome.
Your hair is awesome,
too, man.
I'm going platinum today.
I make a point to
always talk to Dede,
'cause she also makes other
great things that I love.
We're gonna come back.
We'll make
something else, right?
SERVER: Ox tails.
Ox tails are excellent.
They come right off the bone.
One of my favorites.
It's the only place I know
in Oakland that has them.
Give me a minute.
Welcome back.
We're here at Oaktown
at Southern Cafe
with Chef Dede,
and I got to
tell you something --
when you have that
fried chicken fix,
this is the doctor.
So Doctor Dede,
what are we into next?
One of our number-one
sellers, ox tails.
I thought, okay I'm not
sure about the ox tails,
'cause not everyone
can cook ox tails.
So I tried them, wonderful.
I know you like them.
Oh, I am bodied by ox tails.
They are tender and juicy
and they fall off the bone.
Not everybody understands that
it's not really coming from ox.
They're coming from cows,
the tail.
If you can cook it
down the right way,
the depth of flavor, oh.
I already know.
The first part, we'll
dump in a pot here, Guy.
Granulated garlic,
a little salt, Guy.
Doctor.
Black pepper, cayenne.
Cayenne, you girls are getting
after it with the cayenne.
Green bells.
Onions.
Beef base.
You already know.
You cook a little bit,
Guy, you know.
Just once in a while.
Chicken base.
Pour that water in here, Guy.
And then a little
kitchen bouquet.
You already know.
Come on now.
I'll let these go two
hours, medium heat,
and then they'll taste
like a million bucks.
Okay, now what are we
gonna serve them with?
Collard greens.
Okay, do you know that my
middle name is collard green?
It's not, but it should be.
When they're good,
they're really good,
and when they're bad,
I'll still eat them.
We add our smoked turkey
to the water.
You let it boil
for about 30 minutes.
So, the greens have
been cleaned off,
those all go in.
You got a lot going in there.
Gonna put that
salt in here, Guy.
Black pepper, cayenne,
granulated garlic,
smoke flavor base.
There you go.
Red peppers, sugar, put
those onions in there,
a bell pepper, pan-fried oil.
Green vegetables can be dull.
That's giving it
a little sheen.
Add a little flavor
to it, too.
These are gonna cook for two
hours, till they're tender.
And it's gonna get
dangerous right now.
It's about to go down.
Got beans and rice, Guy.
Ox tails.
And the greens?
Oh, those collard greens.
Oh, look at that.
So...
That's how you eat
an ox tail.
You got to get it all.
You really
like those ox tails.
Well, you're cooking them
just right.
The flavor and the depth
and the texture
and the unctuous fat and all
that you get from that ox tail,
you can't get that
out of state.
Greens are good?
Good?
You guys are
fantastic ambassadors
to what folks should look
for in a Southern restaurant.
Thank you, Guy.
Ox tails.
I'm a big fan of ox tails,
and these remind me
of my grandmother.
WOMAN:
I love the collard greens.
You can taste the onions and
the smoked meat that's inside.
It's delicious.
Breaded pork chop, dinner up.
You have to eat it
to believe it.
That should be the
tagline of the restaurant.
"You got to eat it
to believe it."
Nice job.
Right on.
Thank you, Guy.
Watch out for this one.
Watch out.
Thank you, big guy.
So, was this a great
road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
[ Towel squeaking ]
♪♪