Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ooh. Ooh. Ooh!
We're reeling in a full hour
of standout surf...
Okay.
One more lobster.
...and tasty turf...
Oh, my God.
...from around the world.
Nope, you're not tuning in
to the Spanish channel.
This is still "Triple D."
We've got major meats
in Minnesota...
Am I in heaven?
...crab cakes
and pork belly in Jersey...
You did it.
You nailed this one.
...Creole creations
in Mississippi...
Mmm!
...and not-your-everyday
pasta up in Seattle.
Dude, where has this
been all my life?
Plus a high-octane stop
in Charlotte.
Get after that!
And in Havana, Cuba...
That's a delicious dish.
...a seafood combo you
won't find anywhere else.
You're crazy.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in south New Jersey
in a town called Somers Point.
Now, this is
where people cruise through
to go down to the boardwalk
and Ocean City.
But more importantly,
to visit this joint.
This is The Grilled Cheese
& Crab Cake Company.
♪ Down to Somers Point ♪
♪ To a funky little joint
called The Crab Cake Co ♪
It's a catchy name.
Everything is amazing.
Big Bad Fishwich.
Everybody comes in here
and is like,
"Oh, what do you guys serve
here?"
Grilled cheese and crab cakes.
FIERI: And the guy marrying
the two is Steve Novak...
Throw on another crab cake
for the other melt now.
...who bought this place
back in 2010
thanks to a little help
from the family --
brothers pitching in and
grandparents backing them up.
Got to love Grandma.
But Grandma,
she dropped the coin.
Grandma Tarantine.
We call her "G-Tar,"
though.
What up?
And Grandma's investment
is built on a classic.
Who doesn't love grilled cheese?
It's the ultimate comfort food.
WOMAN: You can put anything
inside a grilled cheese,
and he does it the best.
I got the crab melt.
WOMAN:
It's a grilled cheese sandwich,
and it has a crab cake
in the middle.
It's what
they're known for here.
Let's get into it.
All right, so,
the first thing we're gonna do
is add our mayo to the bin.
Next, we're gonna add
our eggs.
Then our fresh lemon juice.
I like to use
honey mustard.
A little sriracha --
I think sriracha
just makes everything better.
Just a little Crystal Hot Sauce,
a little extra heat.
And then
Worcestershire sauce.
Wor-shur-shur sauce.
Old Bay seasoning.
Say "hey" for Old Bay.
There you go.
Your black pepper?
Hey-y-y-y-y.
Actually,
this is celery seed...
[ Both laugh ]
He's at one point
over here.
A little celery seed.
Very nice.
And then baking powder.
A load of
fresh-chopped parsley.
And then
we whisk her up.
She's good to go.
Next, we add
our panko bread crumbs.
So, you want to make sure
it's incorporated in real good.
Now the crab.
Let's talk about that.
Jumbo lump.
Treat it very gingerly now,
correct?
Exactly.
'Cause you don't want
to bust it up.
People like to see
those real big lumps.
My lovely,
crabby lumps.
That is some creamy...
Actually, this will solidify
once it sets.
It's gonna have to.
So, we're gonna throw
a little butter on the grill.
We're gonna take
our crab cake,
put it right on the butter,
butter the bread.
You and butter.
Monterey Jack cheese.
Shouldn't you have it
on a squirt pump or something?
[ Laughs ]
Probably.
We're gonna
steam the bread
just to make sure
we melt the cheese real good.
So, we're gonna let this cook up
on both sides?
This is our crab melt.
Whew. Wow.
Crab cake
is a little bit creamier
than what
most people expect.
Crispy on the outside,
tons of crab.
No question about
the amount of crab in there.
Nice crunch of the toast,
not too much cheese.
You pull it off, man.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
I love it. [ Laughs ]
It's a favorite.
It's moist, it's fresh,
it's delicious.
You can either have it
plain or angry.
"Angry" here means
sriracha and jalapeños.
You make the cheese steaks
angry.
Cream of crab soup --
you can get that angry.
Having the sandwich angry
makes me very happy.
FIERI: And another hit
making folks smile...
I love the pork belly Reuben.
Pork belly Reuben up.
It's one of the most epic
sandwiches on the menu.
We're doing pork belly
here.
We just have
a real simple rub.
We're gonna start
with a little kosher salt.
A little black pepper.
Garlic powder.
Rosemary.
A little bit of oil...
Just so it sticks.
...so it's pasty.
Mix her in.
How about we do this?
Yeah, that works.
So, we give it a rub,
and we leave it
for about 24 hours.
And we're gonna
put it in our roasting pan
and roast it
for three hours.
Word to the pig.
All right, we're making
Grandma G-Tar's sauerkraut.
We're gonna mix up the brine --
apple cider vinegar.
We got our apple cider.
Kosher salt.
Crushed caraways.
Very nice.
We add our cabbage
to the brine.
Back into
the microwave-safe container.
I feel like this is probably
a one-person job.
If you wait out back,
that'd be great.
Good luck with that.
[ Laughs ]
All right, I'm ready.
Do you need me?
Okay, I'm back.
All right. Great.
Gosh, you were able to do that
all by yourself?
Grandma bought me
a restaurant
'cause I could put stuff
in bowls all by myself.
"Put stuff in bowls"!
We cover this bad boy up.
This is gonna go for
about five minutes.
Pork belly.
I like to slice the pieces
pretty thick.
Like buttah.
It's a sandwich.
That's a sandwich?
Take our four slices,
nice hot pan.
A little marble rye.
We got to butter that.
Oh-ho-ho!
We're gonna add
a little Swiss.
Now we cover it,
melt that cheese,
and throw on our kraut.
Top it with sauerkraut.
We add our pork belly.
Hit it with our homemade
Russian dressing.
It's about the most ridiculously
huge sandwich
I've seen in a while.
That's
our pork belly Reuben.
Mmm.
Brother,
I am telling you what.
This has got
a lot of texture to it.
It's got a lot of flavor.
The pork belly's dynamite.
You toasted the bread nice,
even though it's got
tons of moisture around it.
You did it.
You nailed this one.
Mmm.
The only thing you need
when you come in to get that
is a friend to drive you home
and a medical release.
[ Laughs ]
Crazy delicious.
I love everything about it.
He kills it
with the pork.
You're, like, giving it
mouth-to-mouth right now.
You're saving this thing.
Working on it.
We need food like this.
WOMAN: He's making a good name
for himself
and for Somers Point, too.
You love food, you dig people,
you're into this.
Nicely done,
brother.
Thanks.
FIERI: Coming up a garage turned
restaurant in Charlotte...
Whaa!
...going full-throttle
with their burgers...
You're attacking
this thing.
It's like a coyote
got ahold of it.
...and put the killer
crunch on shrimp.
It tastes
like a corn dog.
Straight from the fair.
-Straight from the fair.
♪♪
So, I'm cruising around here
in the Charlotte Motor Speedway.
I think I might be lost,
but I'm looking for
my buddy Clint Bowyer.
What's up, Bowyer?
Let's go
to downtown Charlotte.
Put your seatbelt on.
You might need it.
♪♪
[ Bell rings ]
So, we're on the west side
of Charlotte, North Carolina.
Now,
you remember the Penguin?
Everybody
remembers the Penguin.
Well, it closed,
but the guy, Greg,
opened up a new joint over here
on the west side.
And you know what?
This is
Pinky's Westside Grill.
♪♪
Redneck turf and surf up.
Whoo!
MAN: Love it.
I'm here about
three or four times a week.
This used to be an old garage
that worked on Volkswagens.
That's why there's a Volkswagen
on the roof.
FIERI:
This old garage switched gears
from cars to cooking in 2010
when chef and owner Greg Auten
cruised over
from a legendary local spot.
We met you
at the Penguin
in a funky little joint
in a great time.
That place has closed.
Things have changed.
To see how you reopened,
it's bigger, it's badder,
it's faster than it was.
It's everything from
"Oh, I just want a salad"
or a fat hamburger
with everything on it.
AUTEN:
Triple "G" in the window.
Triple "G" has three patties.
It's got slaw, chili, mustard,
and American cheese.
And why do you call it
the Triple "G" burger?
Because it was Triple "G"
Volkswagen repair.
See, I thought when you called
this the Triple "G" burger
it was
"Guy's Grocery Games."
Even in Charlotte,
it's got to be about Guy.
[ Laughs ] All right.
What do you got, buddy?
We are making our house-made
chili for the Triple "G" burger.
Got it.
80/20 ground beef.
Water going in.
Yellow onion.
Fresh garlic.
Lot of garlic.
That's a good thing.
Chili powder.
Black pepper.
Seasoning salt.
Coriander.
Hot sauce. Cumin.
Okay, so this all cooks down.
Then you add the tomato paste.
Cook it up,
and this will be the chili
that's going on top
of the Triple "G" burger.
Let's cook.
Are you just gonna get
right into the cooking
part of this right now?
Yes. Ready to cook.
This is it --
the Triple "G" burger.
This is what
we've been waiting for, huh?
This is what this place
was founded on.
Three 5-ounce patties.
Stack 'em up, baby.
Stack 'em and go.
Oh, my.
We've got the pound of meat,
three pieces of cheese,
house Southern slaw,
mustard, chopped onions.
And then the chili.
Put this on top.
I want to see you do this.
I don't know how to do this.
Here we go.
[ Laughs ]
Get after that!
Greg, I'm telling you,
it's fantastic.
You're attacking this thing.
It's like a coyote
got ahold of it.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN: Triple "G," sir.
MAN: It's a sloppy piece
of equipment,
but it's delicious and filling.
Shrimp tacos up.
WOMAN: Greg brings up things
that you would think, "What?!"
And when you taste it,
it's just fantastic.
Corn dog shrimp up.
Corn dog shrimp is delicious.
WOMAN:
The corn dog batter is sweet,
and then the shrimp tend to be
a little bit salty.
It's just good.
FIERI: Okay,
what are we making next?
We are making the batter
for the corn dog shrimp.
Dipsy Dog corn dog mix.
That's very old school.
A lot of fairs and circuses
and stuff like that use it.
We're gonna go in
with the water.
Then we're gonna jump on it
with a whisk.
All right, so, you see how nice
and creamy that is?
So it'll really coat
to that shrimp.
Here we go.
♪♪
21-25 shrimp.
Grab them by the tail.
By the tail.
Dunk them in.
Okay.
Got to set them in there
nice and easy.
Float them a bit.
Set it in.
And let it got.
That's so it doesn't
just sink to the bottom.
Bam!
There you go.
Whaa!
Corn dog shrimp
are ready to go.
Perfect them babies are.
Pretty proud of yourself
on these, aren't you?
Yes.
Get in after it.
Oh, yeah.
They're so good.
It tastes like a corn dog --
sweet, crunchy batter.
Straight from the fair.
Not salty.
The corn dog shrimp
is something I've never had,
and I'll be back to Pinky's
weekly because they're so good.
WOMAN: Corn dog shrimp.
The breading they use on there
with the shrimp inside,
it's extra sweet.
It's always fresh shrimp.
It's great stuff.
All the food is right on.
The Asian pork burger.
Asian pork burger is
sweet, tangy.
It's delicious.
What are we making?
Korean barbecue sauce
for the Asian pork burger.
We're going in
with soy sauce.
Sesame oil.
You have that in the South.
Black pepper.
Fresh garlic.
Rice wine vinegar.
Fresh ginger.
One Granny Smith apple.
That's the key
right there.
Sriracha sauce.
I don't know.
That could be it right there.
Brown sugar.
Then we're gonna thicken it
with a cornstarch slurry.
So, this cooks down.
You hold that as the sauce
that goes to the burger?
Mm-hmm.
And now we're into
the pork burger itself.
Yep. We're gonna go in
with fresh ground pork.
We have cilantro, garlic,
green onions,
rice wine vinegar,
five-spice powder,
sesame oil, dried mint,
sriracha sauce.
Big on sriracha.
Sriracha's good stuff, man.
Great.
Sambal chili paste.
Red curry paste.
We basically have everything but
the kitchen sink in this one.
Yes.
Fresh ginger.
Fish sauce.
That's actually an adjustment
on a racecar. You know that?
What? Fish sauce?
No, no. Everything
but the kitchen sink.
It means --
You're all over the tracks.
See? He knows.
Chili flakes.
Curry powder.
Lime juice and mirin rice wine.
All right.
We're just going hands in.
All right. Let these cook up,
put a nice little crust on them.
Yep.
♪♪
Little bit of the glaze.
A cilantro honey slaw.
Okay.
Look how good it is!
♪♪
I just want to show you guys
something --
my first bite
and Bowyer's first bite.
Look at his fuel tank
versus mine.
You know, you always wonder
how these restaurants
get on this show.
You don't wonder anymore
if you try that.
The balance of the flavors,
crunch of the slaw,
really nice bun, by the way.
When the sauce kicks in,
that's the best.
Real deal, man.
Damn right.
Well done.
I'll take another one of those.
Asian pork burger.
It's a nice blend of pork
with a hint of spice,
and it's nice and juicy.
This is Cassi and Marcus Smith,
and my buddy Marcus here
is the president
of Charlotte Motor Speedway.
We love Pinky's, and, I mean,
this burger is unbelievable.
Did you feel the flavor?
Oh!
I mean,
this is Flavortown.
I love this.
Ding Dong Chicken up.
Great good, great atmosphere.
And it's just a wonderful energy
that's here.
I have a cousin named Pinky,
and his real name is Greg,
so Pinky, Greg --
I mean, this was meant to be.
Up next, a wild and wacky
Seattle stop...
The joint is Bizzarro
though, right?
Exactly.
...for some
lights-out linguini...
This has got to be in
the top five I've ever had.
...and ravioli...with elk?
That's like license
to do whatever you want.
♪♪
You know, the Northwest
region of the United States
has some of the most unique and
eclectic restaurants anywhere.
I'm here in Seattle at one
of those joints -- Bizzarro.
Now, with a name like that,
you might expect it to be like
Twilight Zone of restaurants.
Well, the only thing
you can expect here
is the unexpected...
in the vibe...
Why, come with me!
-...and on the plates.
-A little elk.
'Cause the owners, former actor
Jodi-Paul Wooster...
Enjoy.
...and Andrew Bray,
who used to work
in the circus...
Come on in.
...had the good sense
not to play with their food.
The pumpkin ravioli is amazing.
-You're enjoying the bolognese?
-I love the bolognese.
There are people that beg
for the lasagna.
Here comes the shank.
FIERI: Thanks to serious chef
Rob Milliron.
MILLIRON: Puttanesca and an elk.
Whatever is fresh and in season,
that's what I want to
put on people's plates.
FIERI:
Like organic lamb shanks...
Without exception,
one of the best.
...locally grown
mushrooms with penne.
Fresh, organic,
and delicious.
And check out the linguini
in clam sauce...
So good.
...with clams right
out of Puget Sound
and home-cured pancetta.
So, get me started.
I'm gonna slice my pancetta.
House-made pancetta
is the only way to go.
-House-made pancetta?
-A couple pork bellies.
Cover them completely
with salts.
How long
do you salt cure?
-Seven days.
-Awesome.
Take a couple
of these jalapeños.
So, you roasted
the jalapeños.
You know, that mellows
them out a little bit.
You taking ribs
and seeds?
Yep. You get a nice little bit
of heat out of this.
Yeah.
I'm gonna add some olive oil.
Get in the pancetta.
This is gonna take
a second to crisp up.
Okay.
Roasted garlic.
Toss in the jalapeño.
Hit this with white wine.
Take a nice
big whiff of that.
I always like
my white-wine facial.
So, now I'm gonna
add some clams.
And I'm just
gonna cover this.
When those clams open up,
I'm gonna drop
my fresh-made linguini.
You're making
the linguini every day?
Yep.
So this goes
in the pasta cooker.
I'm gonna finish it with a nice,
healthy piece of butter.
So, my clams are
all opened up here.
Add in my pasta.
Let it soak up
some of those juices.
This is called
nesting of the pasta.
So, pasta there...
stands it up so it doesn't
get lost in the bottom.
That broth just
looks out of bounds.
Dude, where has this
been all my life?
Seriously. You got to be
licensed to do this.
This is crazy.
The roasted jalapeño
perfectly complements it.
Nice firm texture
to the pasta.
Mmm! I would challenge
anybody on this one.
This has got to be
in the top five I ever had.
Just keep talking
about random things.
I'm trying to get
as many bites in
as I can in
this segment available.
♪♪
It's got a light,
flavorful, fresh taste.
-The broth is delicious.
-The best I've had.
All the way to Italy --
it's as good as it comes.
-And as fresh.
-You ready for pasta?
You can't match your
actual homemade pasta.
It just absorbs
all the sauces better.
It makes a much
better dish.
Like Puttanesca
with fresh linguini.
I love it because
it's super spicy.
I'm having the
white-truffle ribbons.
FIERI: In a butter sauce with
scratch-made pappardelle.
It melts in your mouth.
It's so great.
FIERI: And even gnocchi with
a cauliflower garlic sauce.
That's ridiculous. Mmm!
Never in a million years.
Can you put a subtitle
on the bottom of that?
I wouldn't have put them
together in a million years.
I mean, I'd do
the cauliflower and garlic,
but not something
heavy as a gnocchi.
It's out of bounds.
Really impressed.
Wow, dude.
Everything
I've had here is great.
Polenta's ready
on the shank.
There's a passion and flair
in everything they do.
-They atmosphere is fun.
-♪ Oh, Chelsea! ♪
[ Holds out-of-tune note ]
[ Whistles ]
If we're not having a good time
here, we wouldn't be doing it.
Ohh, here we go.
It's a great place to be around
a lot of great, creative people.
The joint is Bizzarro
though, right?
Exactly.
That's like license
to do whatever you want.
-A little elk.
-Like mixing elk
in your ravioli sauce.
It's really, really great.
This is
a very Northwest dish
in an Italian
preparation.
You're gonna just add
a little bit of oil.
You know, elk's
a real lean meat,
so I render a little pork fat
from some pork belly.
To sear the elk in it.
-That is flavor.
This is elk shoulder.
It's perfect for braising.
So, it's bone,
rolled, and tied.
Some salt and pepper.
Nice amount of flour
on each side.
Add this in here in
the deepest part of the fat.
All that goodness
cooks in there.
Sear it around
20, 25 minutes.
Well, you crusted
that bad boy.
Definitely.
Pull it out.
Mirepoix.
Onions. Celery. Carrots.
Some nice sweetness
out of that.
Gonna add some salt
and some pepper.
Tart cherries.
Just dried.
Mmm.
Give a little
sweet factor.
I dig it.
Deglaze with a little
bit of red wine.
Add some ground tomatoes.
Well, that's about
as traditional Italian
as you're gonna
get there, brother.
Put this back in.
Cover it with a little bit
of parchment paper
to control the heat.
-How long is this gonna cook?
-About five hours.
The longer the better.
-Low and slow, baby.
Our elk is
nice and braised.
Wow.
"The dice is right."
Bob Barker.
I'm gonna take my meat
and then this braising liquid.
It's gonna
make up the sauce
for our potato
roasted-garlic ravioli.
Nice little toss.
Onto the plate.
-That's a big portion.
-A little ricotta cheese.
Touch of parsley.
Mmm.
It's awesome, dude.
The elk is super,
monster tender.
Succulent.
Not dried out.
Really nice rich flavor.
Not gamey.
I challenge anybody
to tell me
that they don't
like wild game
then have them try that.
Another
stellar dish, man.
Mmm. Come into
this crazy kitchen
and think I'm gonna
get stuff like that?
That's bizzarro.
I just thought it was amazing.
I mean, the sauce picks up
the flavor very well.
-It was great.
-I love everything on the menu.
I come here five nights a week.
It's sort of spoiled me rotten.
We need some red sauce
in about three minutes.
FIERI: One thing I've been
impressed with you today --
you've really had foundation
to why you do it.
And you believe in it.
That's a true chef.
Impressed.
To be able to come
and be in this atmosphere
with great friends
and be able to have a plate
of food like this,
I mean, you can't be it.
They make you feel special here.
-Lovely to see you.
-It's just a fun place to go.
Brr-brr-brr.
Splort.
FIERI:
When people leave Bizzarro,
how do you want them
to describe it?
"Oh, my God.
I just ate at Bizzarro.
What just happened to us?"
Wow.
FIERI:
Coming up on this full hour
of serious surf and turf...
Tranquilo.
...we're headed to Cuba...
Hey! There we go.
...for a shout-out to the
country's most famous chef...
Outstanding.
...and an accidental
crustacean creation.
That's a delicious dish.
♪♪
Never in a million years
would you tell me
that I'm gonna make it to Cuba.
Here I am, "Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives,"
in Havana, Cuba.
And I gotta tell you something,
I'm blown away.
I've wanted to come here
since I was a kid,
'cause of the culture,
the food,
my appreciation for rum,
great cigars.
So I'm in an area
known as Old Havana
in Barbers' Alley.
You ask anybody
where Barbers' Alley is,
they'll be able to tell you.
But I'm here
to check out a joint
that's got such a crazy story.
It's a tribute to a chef.
And I can give you
all the details.
But you have to hear it
to believe it.
This is El Figaro.
El Figaro -- off the chain.
Just knocked it
right outta the ballpark.
Traditional Cuban food
with a little bit
of sophistication.
FIERI: And based on
a lot of history,
something veteran employee
Joan Blanco is proud of.
This restaurant is a museum
for the life of what's
one of the most important chefs
in the Cuban history.
FIERI: His name was
Gilberto Smith Duquesne.
He was the personal chef
of many important people.
Like Frank Sinatra,
Nat King Cole,
Ernest Hemingway
and Brigitte Bardot.
All the food
that we offer here
is the food
that Gilberto cooked.
With Chef Alex Luco
carrying the torch,
making a splash with
this unique Gilberto specialty.
The lobster in coffee sauce.
Lobster in coffee sauce,
it's fantastic.
You need to know the tale
of the recipe.
FIERI: It goes back
to when Gilberto was cooking
for French President
Francois Mitterrand.
So Gilberto take a lot
of coffee.
He was in the kitchen,
cooked his famous lobster,
and the espresso dropped.
How you say
to the president, "Sorry.
The food is bad now,"
you know?
Mm-hmm.
As a good chef, he made it.
He fixed it.
And when Mitterrand
tried that, he said,
"Wow,
I need more like that."
All right, Chef.
Beautiful lobster, look at that.
-And it's fresh.
-Never frozen.
When you do that,
you kill the flavor.
Do you have freezers in Cuba?
Yeah.
Not many.
I don't know.
Okay.
I don't work
in that sector.
"I don't work in that sector."
[ Laughs ]
I'd take this guy anywhere.
Okay.
Salt and pepper.
Not very much pepper.
It's white pepper.
Uh, exactly.
Lime juice, we put olive oil,
the lobster.
So just a little bit
of temperature.
Yeah.
So it's not tough.
The lobster, they will tell
you when it's ready...
"Hey,
it's the next step."
[ Laughter ]
You're crazy.
The onions, butter...
Got it.
Seven-year rum.
[ Whistles ] Very dangerous
with my hair.
A little demi-glace.
Yeah.
Now, the vino blanco.
Capitan...
Okay.
Sí, sí, sí.
Champignon.
Mushrooms...
Yeah.
Parmesan?
A little bit.
Building the layers.
Yeah.
The hot sauce...
Okay.
A little coffee.
Coffee.
Kahlúa? For the lobster
or para tú?
-No.
-Oh. All right.
And crema...
Is the last part.
Oh, we're gonna stuff it back
in the shell.
Beautiful, and what is this?
Albahaca.
Oh, basil.
Bon appétit.
♪♪
That's a delicious dish.
I thought the coffee
was gonna be too strong,
where you weren't gonna
get the lobster.
But not.
Very delicate.
Yeah.
It's not really strong seafood.
It's not just strong coffee.
It's a really good balance.
Excellent.
I know that Cubans love coffee.
Putting it into a lobster tail,
I didn't know.
Outstanding.
-Your lobster, sir.
-It's the best. The best.
Presentation was excellent.
So you know that I would not
come to Havana, Cuba,
without bringin' my family.
So my mom and dad
and of course my wife, Lori.
I've never had anything
like this.
I mean, I love coffee.
I love lobster,
but who ever thought
of putting them together?
It's absolutely delicious.
I don't know how they've been
married together so well.
-Bon appétit.
-[ Laughs ] Merci.
It's very good,
uh, food and good people.
FIERI: Starting
with Gilberto Reina,
known around here as Papito,
who owns the barber shop
that's anchored
this alley for years.
There are a lot of little shops
with different arts.
It just seems to be a street
full of togetherness,
so it gotta have good food.
What else are we gonna make?
Pork in Camagueyana style.
Camaguey is the province.
Pork, sir.
Pork loin, magnifique.
Oh, wrong language.
Magnifico. [ Laughs ]
Lomo...
...de cerdo...
BOTH: ...a la...
...a la...
BOTH: ...Camagueyana.
...Camagueyana.
Huh?
Nope, you're not tuning
in to the Spanish channel.
This is still "Triple D."
Thin-cut pieces
of meat, sauteed peppers,
onions with a light sauce.
It's very good.
Camaguey is the area
in the center of Cuba,
so this is a dish
from that region.
Yeah.
Okay. Beautiful red color
on the pork.
So we put salt.
Okay.
Pureed garlic.
Some ajo.
Lime...
Marinate it a little bit.
Hey! There we go.
White wine.
Okay.
And then, the --
Rosemary, parsley.
Rosemary and parsley.
Demi-glace.
And now, we will prepare...
The sauce.
Yeah. Pepper.
Got it.
The onions, white wine,
and a spoon of demi-glace.
Next?
The final touch is a couple
of minutes cooked together.
Beautiful.
Tranquilo.
[ Laughs ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Hums ]
Namaste.
Okay.
That's pesto sauce.
Pesto sauce.
♪♪
People wanna ask
how to make great flavor.
You gotta start
with fantastic products.
In Cuba, it's all organic.
All organic.
Very simple dish,
but in its flavor profile,
dynamite.
The peppers really have
a fantastic depth of flavor.
The texture of the pork,
the tenderness.
♪♪
That kind of time and attention,
featuring the local products,
handmade by a young chef
like this, outstanding.
If I could get that
in a cubano...
We prefer a sandwich
with that.
Do you?
Yeah.
Figaro.
Fantastic, man.
The chef had it on the money.
It was perfect.
Dad, you've had more pork
than we should talk about.
What do you think?
It's -- it's great.
I haven't had pork
like this, very tender.
So you know that if it's passed
my family's test,
this is the joint you gotta
check out -- El Figaro.
WOMAN: We're definitely
gonna come back,
and I'm gonna tell
everybody I know.
Okay. One more lobster.
[ Laughs ]
Otra langosta.
No. I'm kidding. I'm kidding.
Up next, a Duluth, Minnesota
smokehouse...
Look at this...
...dishing out fish...
It is outstanding.
...piling on the bison...
Humongous flavor.
...and curing up
a meaty masterpiece.
I mean, that couldn't be,
seriously, any better.
♪♪
You know,
everybody has a quest.
For Monty Python,
it was the Holy Grail.
For Ponce de León,
the Fountain of Youth.
And for Guy Fieri,
it's great salumi.
You know, cured Italian meats.
So I'm here
in Duluth, Minnesota,
at the DeWitt-Seitz Marketplace,
where there's a dude
inside that is curin' it,
brinin' it, and smokin' it.
My quest may be over...
at Northern Waters Smokehaus.
Salamini basket.
The smoked meat cured
and salted here? Best in town.
-Smokehaus sampler platter.
-It's good. It's perfect.
The bad boy of the Vikings,
Steve Hutchinson,
and his wife Landyn.
I don't have a salad body.
I know my meats,
and this is good stuff.
This is the Lanzino.
The pork-loin prosciutto.
The Spanish al chorizo.
Am I in heaven?
-And it all started...
-Special to go.
...as Eric Goerdt's home hobby.
I bought a smoker
and was smoking fish.
Then 12 years ago,
he turned pro.
We started making
all of our own deli meats,
and then we built
a sandwich menu.
Their sandwiches
are wonderful.
-Lynn, come get
your French Kiss!
-He makes everything fresh.
Yep. Everything.
Italien.
House-made salami.
DeWitt Seitzer with a pork loin.
Hot chorizo with pepperoncini.
-And get this...
-Bison pastrami.
-Two Pastrami Mommys to go.
-Really juice, really fresh.
Oh, I love it.
Bison pastrami.
Now I'm making the brine.
Salt. Dextrose.
It's corn sugar.
This is sodium nitrate --
the pink salt.
Now we're gonna
stir this up.
Get ready to inject it
into the bison.
-Like, inject it?
-Inject it.
-Seriously?
-Seriously.
Bison eye of the round.
-Eye of the round, right.
And this is --
It'll spray this.
This is awesome.
It draws up the brine
as we pump.
So it's gonna inject
the brine all over
inside the eye of the round.
-Wow.
-You see it expanding?
Yeah.
Got to make sure that
this brine gets everywhere.
Ohh!
Once we pump all of these
with the brine,
put them in this bucket
and pour the brine over them,
we'll add a bunch
of fresh garlic.
And how long will this sit
with this brine in it?
-For seven days.
-Seven days?
So you're just
rotating batches?
Yeah. Get this off.
You see all the garlic on top?
We give this a little rinse
and then we coat it
with a combination of
black pepper and coriander.
Lay it on thick.
You kinda press it in.
And this is gonna go
into the meat smoker.
This is gonna go right
in the meat smoker, you bet.
And what temperature
is this gonna run at?
It's gonna start at 130.
You gradually raise
the temperature up.
So how long
is this gonna go?
Probably about
six, seven hours.
That's awesome.
And these are ready
for the smoker.
-We pop it in.
-In we go.
The wood chips
go here?
This is maple
and hickory wood.
And this is called
a smoke generator.
The hopper turns, drops saw dust
down on that hot plate,
under which is
a heating element,
and the fans suck it in
to the smokehaus.
After seven hours,
we take all of the racks
out of the smokehaus
and we put them in our
walk-in cooler over night.
Look at that.
Look at the color.
Eye of the round is perfect,
not real fatty.
Look, it's raining.
Humongous flavor.
Dude, you should try
doing this professionally.
All right, we're gonna
make the Pastrami Mommy.
Little mayo.
Little mustard.
Lots of pastrami.
Pepperoncinis.
Couple slices
of Provolone.
Lettuce.
There we have it.
I feel guilty.
♪♪
I was drooling.
Mmm.
You killed that.
Can you see the halo?
Right there? Look.
Show them your wings.
Oh, man!
-Pastrami Mommy.
-It's delicious.
You just don't normally
get bison in a lunch-meat form.
Everything is
really really fresh.
And as local as we can get.
-Like this one.
-Whitefish basket, please.
You got it.
Whitefish is quintessentially
Lake Superior.
I've never had
Lake Superior whitefish.
Well, you better.
This is the start of
the smoked whitefish process.
We're gonna make
a very simple brine.
10 pounds of salt.
2 pound brown sugar.
So how long will this fish
sit in the brine?
Two hours.
And how many fish are you able
to do in a smoker at a time?
Typically about 250 pounds.
[ Whistles ]
That's a big fish.
Because we made
that really intense brine,
it's gonna be
a short brining process,
I score them so that brine has
a chance to penetrate the fish.
And then we dump the brine.
I mean,
I don't have much to say.
I'm just sitting here
watching this just in awe.
It's awesome.
Cool.
So, after
the two-hour soak,
you rinse the excess
brine off of them.
We rack it
for the smokehaus.
-Look at this.
-Slide them in.
Seriously,
I want to drive this.
And it goes in the smokehaus
for about six to seven hours.
The Vortron.
I'm getting one of these.
Lori's just gonna have to
deal with it in the house.
GOERDT: Once it smokes, then we
take it into the walk-in cooler.
It cools?
Yep. Over night.
And then it's ready to be eaten.
Awesome.
I eat the whole fish?
You can eat the whole fish.
Peel the skin back,
and then my favorite cracker
in the whole world.
All we need's a cold beer.
Mmm!
You got to be kidding.
-What do you think?
-It's rich, it's flaky.
It is outstanding.
Yeah, whitefish has
a really clean flavor.
Mmm. So balanced.
It's not sweet, it's not salty,
it's not over-smoked.
It's just got this really nice,
easy-going flavor.
Right on. Awesome.
-Smoked whitefish basket.
-It's great.
He just does a great job.
-It's the only place to buy it.
Brother, you don't need
to make anything else.
Then again...
-Salamini basket.
Ah. Salamini.
It's like heaven.
-I'll have the salaminis.
-The salaminis.
That's my passion.
By far the best.
We are making our house-made
dry-cured salamini.
Which means
small-diameter salami.
-Let's rock and roll.
-Ground Berkshire pork.
Berkshire pork.
The bomb pork.
-Plain old salt.
-Okay.
-Then we have fennel seeds.
-Mmm.
-Cracked black pepper.
Dry milk powder.
Dextrose. Corn sugar.
And this is sodium nitrate --
curing salt.
So we have a bacterial inhibitor
throughout the whole process.
Okay.
And then this is just
garlic pureed with olive oil.
So, we mix this
really well.
And we're gonna add
the starter culture.
And the starter
culture is for...?
There's
a fermentation stage
which is gonna take about two
to three days.
Okay.
And what that does it is eats
the sugars that we put in there
and it creates
lactic acid.
And that lactic acid
will lower the PH.
These are all preservation
methods, and not taste methods.
But oddly enough, these
are all contributing factors
to the flavor profile.
Okay.
So, we pack it in
to this sausage cylinder here.
We put it up here.
Crank it down.
-That is awesome.
-These are beef intestines.
And do they have a porosity,
or a breathe?
They definitely do, and that
becomes really important,
because it allows
moisture to escape.
I'm just gonna cut it,
twist it in two links here
so it doesn't come apart.
-So it's gonna hang from there.
And at this point,
we take a weight.
How much weight
will have been lost
before you declare
that it's done?
Most times, we'll pull it out
when it's 25% or 30%,
but I think 40% --
for my taste buds -- is perfect.
So now we're gonna dip them
in a penicillin solution.
It's almost like the penicillin
on the outside of brie cheese.
It keeps the outside
of the salami moist
in the drying process.
-This is awesome!
We're gonna put it
in our fermentation cabinet.
And that's gonna
lower the pH
over this
two-to-three-day period.
Whoa.
As you can see,
that mold has grown
and you can smell
the lactic acid.
Pull these out of here and
take them into our curing room.
Now they're gonna dry
for about 30 days.
Oh, my gosh!
So now we're gonna
hang these up.
This is so cool!
Once we get close to 30 days,
we'll begin to weigh them.
That's where
the 40% comes in.
And then they'll be
ready to eat.
Love it.
Throw this up on the scale
just to make sure it's ready.
And you want to slice
this really thin
so it almost melts
on your tongue.
♪♪
What? The fennel...
right there.
Nice incorporation,
good fat.
I mean, that couldn't be,
seriously, any better.
Awesome. That means
a lot coming from you.
Salamini basket.
Unbelievable.
It melts in your mouth.
It's really the only place I go.
Two Pastrami Mommys.
It's very original
and everything is delicious.
Awesome.
Really hope
to see you back.
Dude,
no question I'll be back.
FIERI: Coming up, in Long Beach,
Mississippi...
[ Whistling ]
A place dishing out
primo prime rib...
I'd like to have a birthday cake
made out of that.
...and serving up
shrimp Creole style.
Mmm. This is fantastic.
One of my favorite places to
live was Long Beach, California,
so you got to know I was stoked
when I found out there's
a Long Beach, Mississippi.
Now, if you find yourself here,
you got to come check out
this crazy shack -- Darwell's.
People around here say
that they're turning out
some top-notch food.
Mmm. Good.
Like nothing else
you've had anywhere else.
Big flavor you want
to keep on eating.
Darwell's has the taste
of the South.
So tender.
And it's so good I'd think
about spiking my hair.
FIERI: From barbecue
to Cajun and Creole...
-It's just real food.
-Sausage plate.
...and has been ever
since Darwell Yeager --
the locals call him "D"...
-And I got a prime-rib plate.
...opened the joint
a few years back.
I like what you got --
real food, real people.
Okay, folks.
And with a little help from
his dad, who's hard to miss...
-New customers.
-Papa D is just Papa D.
We got some natives here,
and some West Coast
people over here.
Sit back and enjoy him.
This is what you're gonna
grow up to be like.
Hopefully.
So that's your
dad's design out front?
-That's Papa D's design.
-And this is your domain?
He started in
the food biz at 15
and then did some
moonlighting in his 20s.
I was
a professional wrestler.
-Hold on.
-That's it, baby.
I mean, did they throw you?
I mean, what was...
Yeah, they did all kinds
of stuff, but my dad told me,
he said, "Son, you need
to get out of the ring
and get back
in the kitchen."
To focus on what he does best.
I was trained by some of
the highest chefs in this area,
on how to put it out,
and how to make it taste good.
And nothing says
Gulf shore cooking
like their shrimp Creole.
This Creole gives me
a good burst of flavor.
-Who made up this recipe?
-This is my recipe. Here we go.
Celery sautéed in
a 1/4 pound of butter.
Why did you blanch
the bell pepper?
So it'll cook
a little faster.
Sautéed onion.
They've been blanched also.
Sauté your vegetables.
Till they're nice and tender.
Creole seasoning.
Old bay seasoning.
Old bay accents
the seafood really well.
Bay leaves.
And minced garlic.
Ah, you see how the flavors
are coming together
and everything's starting
to marry in there?
Well, we've got one important
step that we've got to make.
The smoked sausages. This has
got to go in with the butter.
Bring that fat out
of that sausage.
You want to render that down.
Flour is going down.
Yep, gonna make the roux
right inside there.
Now, I need
the shrimp stock.
You know, I don't sous chef
for many, all right?
Now, did you make this shrimp
stock yourself?
Yes. I did.
About 200 pounds of shrimp
boils down to be about a gallon.
Tomato sauce.
We're gonna let this cook
for about 45 minutes to an hour.
-We're all tightened up?
-We're looking great.
I actually heat
the shrimp to order.
If I preach one thing,
that'll be it --
is that
seafood overcooks.
People go and make this
big vats of gumbos or stews,
then they leave
everything in there.
All it does is just...
Mush.
Either it turns into mush
or turns into beebees.
That's the way to do it.
-That's the way to do it.
It's served over a white,
long-grain, basmati rice.
[ Whistling ]
This is
Southern Creole cooking,
with a little influence
of basmati rice?
It holds the sauces
and it really makes
for a nice presentation.
Mmm.
This is fantastic.
The shrimp is really
nice and tender.
Everything is fresh.
One of the best things
about this is the basmati rice.
It's a nice flavorful rice.
It's light.
Ah, that's great.
That sausage is dynamite.
We eat over in New Orleans
quite a bit.
This is just as good.
And the shrimp are really
fresh and very tasty.
FIERI: And they're serving
them blackened, too.
When you bite
into it, you just know
you're having something good.
FIERI: Like Darwell's take on
a Louisiana favorite, etouffee,
that starts with their
own blackening spice.
-We got paprika.
-Which is the predominant one.
Three-to-one for everything.
You got cayenne pepper.
That's the super spice.
-That's the heat?
You got oregano.
You got thyme.
Black pepper.
Garlic powder --
the holy favorite spice
of all Southern people.
-Of all spices.
-That's right. Blend that up.
You can make your own
blackening spice.
And you can also
adjust the spice
to taste the way
you like it to taste.
And I've kept the spice
backed out of the etouffee
a little bit.
-Let the shrimp carry it.
-There you go.
Mmm. Really nice.
I don't believe
the blackening has to be
so spicy hot
that you can't enjoy it.
-Blackened means flavorful.
-It's a great one.
Thank you.
That's awesome.
All of his food is great.
New Orleans style
cooking flavors,
barbecue that's unbelievable.
Last pan of ribs!
What are you having,
a little pulled pork?
Pulled pork.
It's real good.
-Just one of 18 sandwiches,
from smoked sausage
to serious burgers.
-It's super good.
-What do you get?
I get the prime-rib sandwich.
Mm-hmm.
-Prime?
-Prime.
-Come on.
-Daddy taught me,
if you can't go top of the line,
don't go at all.
So, we're gonna
completely drench the rib
with the soy sauce.
Now we're gonna rub her down
with some good old
minced garlic.
We got
the Creole seasoning.
A little black pepper.
-Pop the onions in there.
-It's gonna go in the oven.
350 degrees
for about 2 1/2 hours.
So, look at that.
We're gonna let this rest,
and then we're gonna go
ahead and slice it.
'Cause you can't slice it hot.
What is that over there?
Is that an extra spoon?
-Ah, what is it?
I want to just look
at how thin that is.
So thin it's hard
to keep it together
after it comes off
the slicer.
You don't need to do
anything to this.
-But he's gonna.
-I'm gonna start off
by letting it start getting
the juices knocked out of it.
I got the onions
and mushrooms here.
We're gonna sauté them
with a little bit of au jus.
Darwell's magic au jus
that we got going on.
That baby's gonna
come out butter tender.
You're killing me right now
'cause I want it medium rare.
Here it comes.
Got a prime-rib home
set up for me right here.
Got to get the dip
in there.
Mmm.
I'd like to have a birthday cake
made out of that.
Big 16-layer birthday cake
made out of this.
That is awesome, dude.
-Mmm.
-It's one of these
that you eat
and everything
runs down your hands.
It's just messy and good.
-The food is fantastic.
Just a great Southern feel
with a little bit of a twist.
FIERI:
Like this Southern classic.
MAN: This can be served any time
of the day you want it.
-Grits with tasso.
-Tasso is a spicy ham.
Spicy smoked ham.
Start with hot boiling water.
Little salt added.
We got the grits.
Dump them right in,
give them a quick stir,
and we're gonna go to about
a 20 to 30 minute
simmer time on this.
Got it to the consistency
that I like to serve my grits.
Some people like them
a little thicker,
some people like them
a little thinner.
Well, I like them to have
a little bit of run to them.
I don't necessarily want
to stand my spoon up in it.
No.
It'll fall over.
Over in this other skillet,
that I've got preheating...
Some whole butter.
Well, the dairy business does
good around your restaurant.
We're gonna have this
butter melting down here.
And now we need
that wonderful tasso.
You can't "passo"
on the tasso.
And now
here's the thing.
There's no set amount
we're using here.
If you like a lot of tasso
in your grits, sauté a lot.
We're gonna put a nice
little 1/2 pound in here.
Get that nice
and sautéed in
so we get the flavor
out of the tasso.
Fresh chopped
green onions.
And nice, sharp,
shredded cheddar cheese.
Into the grits.
Give this a good stir.
We got the grits, we got
the cheddar cheese going,
we got
the nice sauté mixture,
and we're just gonna dump
that right in there.
Now, you see how everything's
starting to come together here?
Good stuff. Good stuff.
I'm telling you, just wait.
Get ready, Guy.
Get ready.
Mmm.
Mmm!
Wow, that's nice.
A glass of sweet tea and you
got it all together, man.
Not salty.
Little spicy out of the tasso.
That cheddar cheese?
Not overpowering.
The right consistency.
I could
put that pot away.
Easily.
It's got a real smooth
Southern flavor.
And the tasso is nice and spicy,
which is a nice contrast
to the creaminess of the grits.
You go to Darwell's, you're
gonna have a good meal.
Consistently good.
You're gonna have a lot of fun,
and you'll be full
when you leave.
WOMAN: Big flavor is food
that can stand on its own,
and Darwell's manages that.
You got a lot to be proud of.
I mean, it's great food.
It's got a tremendous
amount of community to it.
I mean, everybody
knows everybody.
-Good to be here today.
-Good to see you.
When you go to a theme park,
you have your characters.
-We are the characters.
-They're just without the fur.
Well...
not all of us.
Was that
a road trip or what?
But don't worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
You're up!
♪♪
I smoked you!
[ Laughs ]