Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
...we're laying into
some lights-out Latin.
Right now, I just want
to have this whole thing.
Like at a Miami spot...
This is ridiculous,
dude.
...stacking up flavors
from Peru.
Out of bounds.
A North Carolina joint...
There you go.
...serving up specialties
from Panama.
That's a game
changer right there.
And in Tucson...
Wow!
...Mexican with a
funkalicious twist.
It's delicious.
I'm not kidding you.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina,
right on the edge of
Wrightsville Beach,
at the intersection
of Wrightsville Avenue
and Wrightsville Avenue.
No, really, that's true.
Sounds confusing, but
what's even more confusing
is I'm here to check out
a Panamanian restaurant
that's really well-known
for their great ropa vieja.
So, of course, you'll expect
the name is called...
Ceviche's?
♪♪
Chorizo burger.
It really is great
on so many levels.
Sancocho.
As authentic as I'm gonna
see without physically
being in Panama.
FIERI:
Which is where Hunter Tiblier
grew up while his dad was
working on the Panama Canal.
Now, after 26 years
in the U.S. military,
he and his wife, Laura,
are bringing the flavors
of his childhood
to North Carolina.
Had you worked in restaurants
before, Master Sergeant?
Zero.
-Where did you learn to cook?
-Self-made.
So, what do we do
at Ceviche's?
We do a lot of
Latin-inspired dishes.
Ropa is one of the
national dishes of Panama.
MAN: The ropa vieja is
shredded slow-cooked beef
on a bed of coconut rice.
WOMAN: You have the avocado.
Then you have the
plantains on the side,
and it's just to die for.
So, the first one we're
working with is ropa vieja.
So, this is
one of my favorites.
So, you know
what it means.
-The clothes, baby.
-Shredded clothes, yes.
So, we start with
the flank steak.
That's a lot
of Worcestershire.
Oh, you got to
infuse it.
Red wine, salt,
peppercorn, some oregano.
There you go.
Garlic, bay leaves,
and onions.
We add our water.
Bring it up to a boil.
About three hours, we'll
start checking the meat.
Then we shred the meat up.
Okay.
-May I?
-Definitely.
I have my fingers
all over it.
Can I have some of this?
Get it away from me.
I'm gonna eat it all right now.
Just one more piece.
We're gonna build
citrus cabbage slaw.
Start off with green cabbage,
purple cabbage,
red bell peppers,
jalapeños, green onions.
-Pickling juice.
-Pickling juice?
It has vinegar, sugar, and
a little beet juice in it.
Huh.
-And a little salt.
-Or a lot of salt.
And some black pepper.
We let this sit
about 20, 30 minutes.
Now we're building
the rest.
Start off with some oil.
Okay.
Red onions, yellow onions,
green bell pepper,
red peppers,
some more oregano,
beef broth strained
from earlier.
All that flavor
that's inside of it.
Tomato sauce, red wine vinegar,
red wine, ginger.
A lot of ginger.
And Worcestershire.
Watch your sister sauce.
Then the meat.
Give this a stir.
Let that cook
for another hour.
So, the final step?
We got Roma tomatoes,
green peas, green olives.
You got to have the
brininess of the olive.
Cilantro.
Give it a couple minutes.
Then you're done.
We'll plate the ropa
over the coconut rice.
Beautiful slaw.
Some fried plantains.
Our salsa fresca,
green onions.
Then an avocado.
This is like pass-out food
for me.
♪♪
So, the key is here,
you got to get a little
bit of that slaw,
some of the rice, little
bit of that fried plantain
all at the same time.
That's when you're
getting a real bite.
'Cause I don't see traditionally
on most ropa vieja
it comes with all this.
Right now, I just want to
have this whole thing.
Excellent dish.
Well done, my friend.
I have a ropa vieja.
The meat is juicy.
The coconut rice
complements it perfectly.
The coleslaw is
totally delicious.
Real deal.
It's very similar to what
I had down in Panama.
FIERI: And so is the dish that
gives this place its name.
Langoustine ceviche.
This place is
called Ceviche's.
The ceviche better be good,
and it's the best I've ever had.
It's always fresh --
local fish and local seafood.
HUNTER: My dad taught me
how to make ceviche,
and throughout my
military career,
just made
a lot of ceviche.
FIERI:
And from there, he's added
plenty to his bag of tricks.
WAITRESS:
I have your sancocho.
Like this Central American take
on old-school chicken soup.
We're gonna do the Panama
national dish of sancocho.
What does "sancocho" mean?
"Chicken soup."
-Duh.
-[ Laughs ]
First, some
garlic-infused oil.
We'll add in
the chicken, oregano,
and our house seasoning.
Salt, black pepper,
and garlic powder.
Next step, we got some
sweet potatoes, carrots,
green plantains.
There's somebody freaking
out at home right now,
going, "Bananas?"
Corn, green onions,
yucca, culantro.
Culantro is like a
kicked-up cilantro.
We add cilantro.
And a bunch
of chicken stock.
Looks like someone took the
blender to the garden.
So, I let it sit
for an hour, then...
-And that's all she wrote?
-That's all she wrote.
Sancocho - one of
Panama's comfort foods.
♪♪
This is great.
I like that there's
the dark meat in there.
Now, when someone
comes in from Panama
do they put the rice in it?
They'll put
a little rice in it.
We have a hot sauce in
Panama called aji chombo.
Wow, that's good.
You got to have it
with that sauce.
That's a game
changer right there.
Oh, definitely.
You really almost go to,
like, South American gumbo.
-Oh, yeah.
-Well done.
HUNTER:
I got sancocho!
There's something
magical about that soup.
We grew up on this.
Aji chombo -- he makes
this from scratch.
There's nothing else
like this.
Frijoles y arroz.
Wow.
I'm right back in Panama.
It makes my heart very happy.
I dig the whole story.
Great that you got
to grow up in Panama,
you come and serve
our country,
and you're self-made
and self-taught,
and you take a lot
of pride and passion in it.
Food's great.
Well done, brother.
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
a mister and missus
in Miami...
Fantastic!
...putting their love
on the line...
-You're crazy.
-No!
Yeah!
I like it.
...all in the name of
their buns -- seriously.
It's actually giving
me goose bumps.
Oh, yeah.
Turn them all on.
♪ Dun, dun, dun,
dun, dun, dun, dun ♪
♪ Dun, dun, dun, dun,
♪♪
So, I'm here in the Kendale
area of Miami, Florida.
I'm just a few miles away
from Scully's Tavern.
You remember that.
We're here on Sunset Drive
to check out a joint
where this Peruvian couple
are taking Peruvian sandwiches
to a whole nother level.
You got to love the name --
Mr. and Mrs. Bun.
♪♪
Barbecue chicken
wing sandwich.
Old-fashioned cooking
with new tastes and flavors.
WOMAN:
Short rib sandwich.
It's got finer
culinary touches to it.
It's like a Peruvian fusion.
FIERI: Put together by
two Peruvian pros --
Gian Carlo Accinelli
and Vanessa Rivera,
aka Mr. and Mrs. Bun.
I got the buns.
You have three.
Thanks to the
signature bun recipe
they developed when they dove
into the sandwich biz.
MAN: I've never had buns
like these before.
They're warm, they're soft,
a little bit of
crunchy on the outside.
It's very light,
very fluffy,
nice crust --
beautiful.
Let's go.
This is high-gluten
flour, sugar, salt,
dried yeast, warm
water, whole milk.
So, now we go
to the mixer. How long?
It's about two minutes.
And 4 1/2-ounce buns.
-4 1/2.
-Yes, sir.
-And how good are you?
-I am very good.
Let's see.
5.2.
[ Laughs ]
4.6.
Okay, let me see,
let me see.
4.4!
[ Laughs ]
Let's see.
Look, look, look.
Oh. 4.2.
You just take it right here
and just ball it up.
That's correct, yes.
And then we'll go
to the oven.
400 degrees,
8 minutes.
FIERI: Then they're topped
with favorites from Peru.
Asado con palta.
Asado con palta, the
meat is so tender.
It's a traditional Peruvian dish
like Grandma used to make
made into a sandwich.
-So, what is asada? Asado?
-Asado is a stew.
-Putting a stew into a sandwich.
-Exactly.
Eye of round roast.
Eye of the round roast --
got it.
Prime --
USDA prime, because --
Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
This little
mom-and-pop bun shop
is using
prime eye of round?
Yes.
Salt and pepper.
We're gonna sear it.
Just vegetable oil.
-Tops are nice and seared.
-Nice. Okay.
We're going to
glaze with Merlot.
-Mirepoix...
-Fantastic
...carrots, celery,
and red onions.
Bay leaves.
Hongo de pino.
Hongo de pino!
I have no clue
what Hongo de pino is.
It's a Peruvian
dried mushroom
behind the pine tree.
Hongo de pino.
You might know me.
I am Hongo -- Hongo de Pino.
You're the villain,
and I'm Hongo de Pino.
[ Laughs ] The hero.
I'm the hero!
Of course I am,
'cause I'm Hongo de Pino.
-Peruvian oregano.
Crushed tomatoes
and chicken stock.
We put this meat back in.
How long will it cook?
2 1/2 hours.
And then what are we
gonna do with the jus?
You're gonna use that
to make the sauce?
Absolutely, yes.
So, taking out
the bay leaves.
But otherwise, you'll
puree the whole thing?
-Exactly.
-Okay, Chef. Let's go.
We let them cool
for 24 hours.
Got it.
And then
just slice it thin.
So, meat...
Sauce...
And then more sauce.
Exactly.
That's the one
we just made.
Nice, fluffy,
beautiful, warm bread.
Slice it.
This is pork belly fat.
So, we toast it up.
House-made mayonnaise.
Three pieces of meat. Nice
and fresh slice of avocado.
Super-crispy fresh
fried onions on top.
What is the rest of this?
Oh, this is the
aji de gallina bites.
Rice, shredded chicken,
and a cheese sauce.
Aji de gallina bites.
It's like arroz con pollo,
but with some cheese fried up.
And what's
the side sauce?
This is the same juice
we used cooking the meat.
♪♪
That is, without question,
one of the best sandwiches
I've had in a long time.
No way.
The bun's fantastic.
It's light, it's fluffy.
It's actually giving
me goose bumps.
Oh, yeah.
Fried onions are dynamite,
meat is really tender,
but it's the jus.
It's the earthiness
of that mushroom.
I'm not kidding you,
bro.
That is out of bounds.
Thank you.
I want to eat
that whole thing
and then sleep in
the parking lot.
Fantastic!
-Thank you very much.
Asado con palta guys.
Table 6, please.
The palta de asado
is totally delicious,
and the dipping sauce is
one of my favorite things.
There's the avocado.
There's the little
crunchy fries in it.
It's just amazing.
All right, guys,
order in, please.
This is my favorite
hole in the wall,
and I love the story
behind the restaurant.
You and your partner...
I always say "my wife."
You didn't
legally get married
because you took the wedding
money to open the restaurant.
Yes. We cannot be
Mr. and Mrs. Accinelli yet,
but we are
Mr. and Mrs. Bun.
-You're crazy.
-No!
Yeah!
I like it.
Enjoy, guys.
I fell in love with her story
before I fell in love
with her food.
Pork belly
and soft-shell crab.
So, here's the deal.
We're hanging out
at Mr. and Mrs. Bun.
I just had
a Peruvian sandwich
that will absolutely
change your day.
When we come back, we're
gonna make something else.
-I don't know what it is.
-Pollo Chi Jao Kai.
That's what I thought.
Pollo Chi Jao Kai.
It's like a fried chicken.
It's got almost, like,
an Asian style to it.
And I'm Hongo de Pino.
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back.
I'm hanging out
at this fantastic
Peruvian sandwich shop.
It's called
Mr. and Mrs. Bun.
Cutting buns for asado.
MAN: There's nothing
like the buns here.
It's soft on the inside, but the
outside has this crispy texture.
They just blend with every
sandwich that they have here.
Pollo Chi Jao Kai
sandwich.
The Pollo Chi Jao Kai,
it's a little thigh meat
that's deep-fried,
has Asian seasonings.
Just delicious.
The Pollo Chi Jao Kai is a
traditional dish in Peru.
This is one of the
Chinese influences.
Is there a lot of
Chinese influence in Peru?
-Lots.
-Really? Okay.
First of all, this
is for the marinade.
Soy sauce, oyster
sauce, sesame oil,
fermented
black bean paste.
One of my favorites --
lot of funk.
Chinese five spices and
just a little bit of salt.
And how long are we gonna let
the chicken marinate in that?
Two days --
48 hours.
-Really?
-Yes.
So, we make the
Chi Jao Kai sauce.
Garlic cloves, soy sauce,
oyster sauce, sesame oil,
sugar, salt,
and chicken stock.
Now that it's boiling,
we'll put the cornstarch
to thicken it up.
I think cornstarch was
made for Chinese food.
And we're gonna
dredge the chicken in...
Flour, egg,
and cornstarch.
Our chicken is just
getting out of the fryer.
You want to choose
your bun?
That one.
Same thing, a little
bit of the pork fat?
Correct.
Chi Jao Kai sauce --
the one we made.
What is Chi Jao Kai? What does
it mean, "Chi Jao Kai"?
-I don't really know.
-Okay, very good.
[ Laughs ]
So, we sauce
the chicken first.
Okay.
Our bun is ready.
A little bit more sauce.
Romaine lettuce.
It's a chicken
with the sauce.
Pico, turnips,
and carrots.
Okay. And then
a lot of chicharróns?
Yes, pork rinds
with a truffle oil.
Can't beat that.
That is moist chicken.
♪♪
This is ridiculous,
dude.
I got to be honest, when you
said the name Mr. and Mrs. Bun,
I'm like, "Come on,"
but the bun is that great.
To call that an Asian
chicken sandwich
is, to me,
really limiting
because there's so many
other flavors going on.
The balance of
what you did,
how you did it,
how long it marinated,
how you cooked it,
what you added to it --
just all these little,
simple factors --
the sum of it is
just ridiculous.
You're dangerous.
Fantastic, brother.
Fantastic.
Thank you.
The Chi Jao Kai.
It's crispy,
but it's not too fried.
And the sauce
is what makes it.
What do you think
of this sandwich?
This is the -- I don't even
know how to pronounce
any of the names,
'cause he says them so fast
and he makes them sound
so cool.
The crunch on it
is excellent,
and the flavor comes out
right at you.
Beautiful --
the slaw on top.
Soft-shell crab.
What I love most about the food
is that it's consistently good.
MAN: He's been able to transport
those flavors from Peru.
This brings back memories to me.
Outstanding. I mean, like
real-deal stuff, bro.
-Nice. Thank you very much.
-You got to come meet this guy.
FIERI:
Coming up, in Tucson...
Gosh, that's good.
...a whole new take
on Mexican...
That's like enchilada
sauce gone wild.
...you got to taste
to believe.
I'm making a plate and
I'm sending it home.
♪♪
So, I'm here in
Central Tucson, Arizona,
and one of the things
you know about me by now
is I love full-flavored food.
I don't care who makes it, I
don't care where it comes from,
I don't care what the in--
what the ingredients are.
But switching gears,
my sister Morgan --
what did she always tell me?
"You got to give
vegetarian food a chance."
So this is what I got for you.
I got vegetarian, I
got full-flavored food,
and it's Mexican.
You're gonna love it.
This is Tumerico.
♪♪
Huevos rancheros are up.
WOMAN: I'm not a vegetarian,
but I come here
because the food is delicious,
it's filling, it's healthy.
FIERI: Which is exactly the
point for Wendy Garcia,
who was born in Mexico and
came to the States at 17.
I grew up eating meat,
but I came here,
and it was, like,
fried food, fast food.
So she ditched
the carnivore life
and started cooking
things her own way.
Turmeric curry up.
She uses very natural foods that
are unique to our surroundings.
FIERI: Like nopales,
which are the pads of
the prickly pear cactus
growing here in
the Sonoran desert
that she's turning into tacos.
Nopalitos.
I love cactus.
I grew up eating cactus.
Just gonna scrape them.
If you want to think
about scaling a fish,
you're scaling a cactus.
We're gonna boil the
nopalitos for 20 minutes.
Then make the sauce.
Hit it.
We're gonna do cashews.
If you've never had cashew
cream or cashew butter,
you're missing it.
Water, lime juice.
We got a little soy flavor
going here with the tamari.
Cilantro and oil.
This is gonna
blow your mind.
♪♪
Gosh, that's good.
People don't know the
power of the cashew.
You're super right.
All right, Chef, now we're
gonna go to the sauté pan.
Nopalitos.
I do onions, and then we're
gonna add the sauce to it.
Break this down for me
while those are cooking.
What do we have?
We got pinto beans
with ranchero sauce.
Delicious.
Basmati rice, cilantro,
lot of lime.
Oh, my gosh.
The rice is fantastic!
I'm loading the nopalitos.
A little cabbage here,
a little pico.
And we'll top it off
with some cashew cream.
I love cilantro
on everything.
♪♪
Mmm!
It's delicious.
I'm not kidding you.
You've got this really
deep, rich flavor.
You got a nice crunchy
tortilla, the crema.
You got a nice pico, and then
the setup behind it.
I mean, seriously, got to
keep it away from me.
It's fantastic.
Don't touch it.
[ Laughs ]
Nopalitos tacos.
WOMAN: Cactus isn't something
I thought I would enjoy,
but it's really flavorful.
I love it. I would be here every
day if this were close by.
Butternut squash tamales
are up.
So, my little sister --
that's my sister Morgan
right there --
she taught me so much
about vegetarian cooking.
FIERI: Like what's possible
with the jackfruit.
So, jackfruit, if you
cook it the right way,
it's gonna give you almost,
like, this pulled pork texture.
Which makes jackfruit perfect
for her meat-like
but meat-free carne asada plate.
We're gonna put the carnitas
on the carne asada plate,
but what else
do we serve with it?
Eggplant chicharróns
and then some soy chorizo
from tofu.
Let's get into it.
We're gonna make carnitas
with adobo sauce.
So, we had the jackfruit that's
been broken out and steamed.
We do garlic, black
pepper, Mexican oregano.
See how big that
flower is on there?
-Really nice big flavor.
-And salt.
Into the fryer,
just like that?
Yeah.
-So, the next thing...
-Yeah, the whole sauce.
Morita peppers.
Moritas?
They're
a little bit creamier.
Oh, it smells awesome.
You got to smell the smoke.
Oh, sorry.
Salt.
Achiote made
from the annatto seed
gives it this great color,
great flavor.
Black pepper,
garlic powder,
lime juice,
oil, water.
That's like enchilada
sauce gone wild.
Yeah!
Okay, Chef,
soy chorizo.
Okay, tofu.
So, I think tofu
gets a bad rap.
But you're gonna
get a chance now
to try it with all
these seasonings
and get to see it
cooked up.
Oh-ho, you're gonna change your
attitude about tofu.
Salt, achiote.
Go heavy on this.
Chili powder, Mexican
oregano, garlic powder.
Turmeric --
beautiful color.
Lime juice.
Okay, let's do the
carne asada plate.
Fantastic.
Carnitas first,
the adobo,
and then we're
gonna do the eggplant to it.
Dust it with corn flour,
salt, and pepper.
Then we do
a little chorizo.
So, right now, if you're
tuning in, don't worry.
It's all meat,
as far as you know.
Eggplant chicharróns.
Jackfruit carnitas
right there.
Beautiful.
Soy chorizo, salad,
pico, cabbage,
a little cilantro, and then it
gets a little cashew cream.
Corn tortillas for these.
Here we go --
the jackfruit.
♪♪
It is ridiculously good.
Even when you look
inside of the taco,
you see pulled pork.
That with the adobo
on it,
there's no way anybody
could tell the difference.
Yay!
-Let's do chorizo.
-Have the chorizo.
♪♪
[ Man laughs ]
Ohh!
Perfect spice.
Perfect amount of salt.
And you got the balance of the
seasoning and the flavors.
My mom and dad would lose
their mind over this.
I'm gonna call my mom.
So, mom, this is Wendy.
Wendy, this is
my mom, Penny.
So, in this plate,
the chicharróns
are made out of eggplant,
the carnitas is made
out of jackfruit,
and the chorizo is
made out of tofu.
PENNY: Wow.
I'm making a plate and
I'm sending it home.
I'm salivating right now.
I want some.
I had to get
the mom seal of approval.
Wow.
Carne asada plate up.
Seasoned with magic, I guess,
'cause it's perfect.
Good friends of mine,
Laurie and Rick.
I mean, this is
a meat-and-potatoes
guy right here.
-What do you think?
-It's wonderful.
I cannot believe that
this is a vegan dish.
If I didn't tell you
that it wasn't pork,
you wouldn't know.
I still don't
believe it.
[ Laughs ]
Tacos al pastor up.
Delicious food is delicious
food. And this is fabulous.
I wanted this to be great
because I don't think
that vegetarian food
gets the right rap.
You guys don't
want to miss this.
Thank you, Guy.
Watch out for this
girl -- the bomb.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for
you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Man, I wish I had some
big cactus pieces
to be throwing
stuff on the floor.
Look, we're having
a party! Whoo!
[ Laughs ]