Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners, drive-ins,
and dives.
This trip...
Whoo!
...we're searching for
culinary treasures...
[ Whispers ] Shh.
Keep it between us.
...and making some
delicious discoveries.
That would be
one of the stars.
In Dallas...
The jefe.
...a legit taco joint
with some surprising spins.
You could cook your shoe
in that good.
And an Afghan spot that charters
first-time territory.
That's one dish.
Plus, a true hidden gem
in Columbus, Ohio...
It's so fantastic.
...taking us on an outrageous
international expedition.
This is one of
the most unique dishes
I've ever tried
on "Triple D."
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
This week on "Triple G,"
four chefs are gonna
battle it out in one c--
No, Chef.
"Triple G" was last week.
This week's "Triple D."
Oh, that's right!
This is a place that's serving
the Tibetan specialties
that you'll want "Mo" of.
This is Momo Ghar.
♪♪
LAMA: Vegetable Jhol Momo.
I've traveled to the Himalayas
and what they do here,
they absolutely nail it.
Kothey.
It's like most unique
experience you could have.
We have Alu Momo.
WOMAN: I actually was just
shopping in the grocery store
and walked past it
and was like, "What is this?"
FIERI: This is one of Columbus,
Ohio's hidden treasures,
where Phuntso and Pramod Lama
are cooking up Tibetan
and Nepalese specialties
smack in the middle
of an international market.
I came here
to do my grocery,
then I noticed a sign
that said "store for rent."
FIERI: Next thing, here
comes Momo Ghar.
And you named it
Momo Ghar because...?
Momo is the number-one
food of Nepal.
Eastern Tibetan Momo.
Momo is a Nepali-
and Tibetan-style dumpling.
Jhol Momo.
My favorite Momo
is the Jhol Momo.
It's a flavor-filled dumpling
drenched in a very spicy sauce
that tastes like nothing
you've ever had before.
-So, what are we gonna make?
-Jhol momo.
Jhol basically means
"sauce" in Nepali.
-Let's do it!
-Some oil in here.
Fenugreek seed.
Onion.
Mixture of chili
and the seasoning for this.
We have garlic, ginger,
salt, pepper,
pureed tomato.
Got to let it simmer
for about 20 minutes.
Toasted sesame seeds.
I have cilantro.
So, basically what we've made,
ladies and gentlemen,
is some Tibetan
tomato sauce.
Yes.
I like it.
Next, we're gonna make
the seasoning for the filling.
Okay.
My spice mix here.
It's similar
to the Indian garam masala.
So, a curry garam masala.
Black pepper. Salt.
Fresh ginger. Garlic.
So you ground
the chicken in house.
Yes.
I have my chopped onion.
Cilantro.
The mixture.
Mixture, yep.
Now, what is the wrapper
that we're putting this in?
It's just flour and water.
So one momo
is that big, huh?
[ Whistles ]
No.
It'll feed all your crew.
I'm here by myself.
[ Laughs ]
So, this little
push, pull, turn,
don't run your fingers
over it,
that's how
you do it each time?
Yes.
I would've run over
my fingers by now eight times.
So, I'm gonna fill this
with the chicken we just mixed.
Okay. Looks like
a soup dumpling.
It looks exactly
like a soup dumpling.
Fatter in the middle
and thinner on --
Yeah, "fatter in the middle"
is my motto.
How many of these
do you make in a day?
A couple of thousand.
Only 997 more to go.
More to go, yes.
Okay.
[ Laughs ]
Steam for about 9 minutes.
Okay.
So, I have heated
some water there.
-For the momo sauce.
-Yes.
Salt.
Chili pepper.
And last but not least,
a couple spoons of
the fenugreek tomato sauce.
Three spoonfuls.
That's five.
Now going on six.
Can I get seven,
seven, seven?
Can I get eight?
Next, lemon juice.
I can already sense I'm gonna
be going into a momo como.
Take some of the sauce
we just prepared.
Cilantro.
I don't know to eat it
or wade in it.
♪♪
Oh, my God.
I'm getting a little bit
of depression right now.
There's only 7 1/2 left.
[ Laughs ]
They are tremendous flavor!
♪♪
The garlic and the onion
and the ginger are all cooked
but still have texture
to them.
I can't shovel them
in fast enough.
Momo masterful.
They are so good.
Thank you, Guy.
Jhol Momo.
What I love about it
is the luxurious broth.
It's got a lot of heat.
Easily the best
dumplings in town.
You wouldn't expect being able
to get so many good things here.
It's like the market
at culinary Disneyland.
Anything Asian you'll
find under this roof.
Asian? Anything in the world,
you can find here.
One day we were looking
for some canned jack fruit,
and then we saw Momo Ghar
and we were like, "Oh,
we better try it."
We're hanging out
in a gigantic
ethnic supermarket
in Columbus, Ohio.
When we come back...
we're gonna make
something else?
Yes. We're gonna make our --
We're not gonna tell them.
Okay.
We'll be back
in just a momo moment.
♪♪
Welcome back here at Momo Ghar.
That was a momo mouthful.
You serve inside
of this dumpling
flavors that are
from all over --
India, Tibet, Nepal.
FIERI: Which makes sense,
since Phuntso Lama
is of Tibetan descent
and was raised in Nepal.
And along with
her husband Pramod,
she set up shop in an
international grocery store
to serve a sampling
of their heritage.
-I have two Chhoila Set.
-Chhoila Set.
It's grilled chicken,
potatoes, black-eyed peas...
It's unique and very tasty.
What are we making next?
Chhoila.
You can make it
with any kind of meat,
but we like to make it
with chicken here.
All right.
We have cumin,
black pepper, turmeric,
salt, garlic, and some oil.
This is just the marinade
for the chicken.
This is a very Nepali dish.
Okay.
They serve this
during festivals,
and it's supposed
to be served cold.
Yeah, the United States would
call it "cold chicken salad."
Yeah, it is similar.
Yeah.
This is the Nepali
chicken salad.
Yes.
And how long are
we gonna let this marinate?
Two hours.
All right,
now we grill it.
So, the chicken's
grilled, cooled...
you cut it -- next?
Add a little leek.
Okay.
This is the cumin.
Paprika. Chili.
Black pepper. Salt.
Fresh garlic.
Fresh ginger.
That's it.
And what's this?
That's a little bit
of mustard oil.
Whoo!
Not yet.
I put it at the end.
Good!
Okay, Chef,
black-eyed peas.
Yes. Potatoes.
Yes.
That's what I thought.
So next,
I have the hot oil.
So, she's got
the fenugreek in the oil.
Now we add in the turmeric.
♪♪
Right on top of it.
Yep.
Everybody gets
the fenugreek/turmeric oil.
Yes.
A little bit
of mustard oil.
[ Whistles ] Coconut?
No.
Flattened, beaten rice.
That's what I was gonna say.
I will put some here.
FIERI: Okay.
Potato salad.
Yep. Black-eyed peas.
And chicken.
Cilantro.
So do I mix it together?
You want to get a little bit of
the rice and one of the sides.
♪♪
You nailed it.
This is one of
the most unique dishes
I've ever tried
on "Triple D."
The textures and
the flavor profiles --
they're so different.
But it's so fantastic.
You've got the creaminess
of the potatoes,
the tenderness of the beans,
tons of flavor
out of the chicken.
That's outstanding.
Thank you, Guy.
Chhoila Set.
Just the combination
of the different dishes.
They're all distinct,
but they all work together.
-Baara. One and two.
-Everything is fresh.
They're making it
right in front of you.
And we clean
the plate every time.
Where do you buy the rice?
Aisle what?
Aisle 18.
Aisle... I'm gone.
Nice job.
FIERI: Up next in Dallas...
It doesn't stop.
...an out-of-bounds
ethnic adventure...
Once you bite into this,
you go a whole different
direction in flavor.
...that "Triple D"
has never experienced before.
This helps people
to better understand
a culture they don't
know anything about.
[ Indistinct P.A. announcement ]
Oh, they're calling me
to the front desk. I got to go.
[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: I'm here
on Greenville Avenue
in Dallas, Texas,
to check out a "Triple D" first.
A "Triple D" first
after 1,000 restaurants?
Are you kidding me?
I never saw this coming.
But it's true,
ladies and gentlemen.
Our first Afghan restaurant.
This is Nora Restaurant and Bar.
♪♪
Mantoo. Table one.
Pick it up.
Man, it is so much flavor.
Wonderful spice palate.
A complete change of pace.
Nora's Salad.
When you look at a plate,
you see a masterpiece.
FIERI: And the artist here
is Matt Pikar,
who left Afghanistan
when he was a kid,
but later returned to learn the
culinary craft of his homeland.
How would you
describe Afghan food?
Flavorful. The spices --
Turmeric. Cardamom.
Saffron.
Once you come and try it,
then you fall in love.
-I need my Bulanee.
-Bulanee's coming.
It is such a great blend
of gourmet and comfort food.
The Lamb Shank for you.
-Oh, baby.
-The Lamb Shank is fabulous.
MAN: And then the rice that
accompanies it is fantastic.
Like, explosion of
flavor in your mouth.
Okay, what are we gonna
make first?
Lamb shanks.
In a pressure cooker.
We go with the garlic.
Onions. Chopped tomatoes.
Fresh cilantro.
Cilantro's big
in Afghanistan?
Oh, yeah. We go salt,
black pepper.
I like the turmeric.
Oh, I love it.
Coriander. Yeah.
Coriander?
How long are we
gonna let this cook?
About 20 minutes.
Just where it's pull-apart
tender but not falling apart.
Yeah, exactly.
Got it.
I love the pressure cooker.
Now we're gonna
continue the process.
So, I put my tomato first.
Then we put the...
Sun-dried tomatoes?
Chile de árbol. Black pepper.
And some paprika.
So, Afghan has a little heat.
Got a little bit,
but not too much.
Take some tomato paste.
Okay.
Then you take
your lamb shank.
Beautiful shanks.
Now this is gonna go
in the oven for how long?
45 to an hour. 350.
And then we're gonna
serve this on top of what?
Qabili Palao.
It's basmati rice,
boiled and steamed.
Nice and light and fluffy.
One of my favorites.
We're gonna take
the saffron water.
-A little saffron water.
-Pour it into the lamb stock.
All the leftover lamb stock
from when you made it before.
Then we have
the seven spices.
Seven spices.
What's in there?
Cumin. Coriander.
Black pepper.
Green cardamom.
Black cardamom.
Clove. And cinnamon.
Then we put
more cardamom in.
Then we put the salt.
Then the last part...
Is more of the saffron.
We mix that together.
In the oven.
25 minutes.
Okay, Chef. Next step?
The topping for Qabili Palao.
We're gonna put the water.
The carrots.
So just a quick blanch.
Then we get the pistachio.
The raisins.
Raisins big
in Afghani food?
Oh, yeah.
Blanched slivered almonds.
He doesn't stop.
Sugar. Cardamom. Saffron.
Some oil.
Beautiful.
We take our lamb shank...
Nicely done.
...put more rice
on top of it.
Then we get the topping.
And that's it.
That's it.
The plate is beautiful.
That's really good.
Thank you.
All of a sudden,
you get a little salt note.
Then you get
a little sweet note.
Then you get some crunch from
the almonds and the pistachio.
It's definitely
the cardamom...
really there.
The fact that you're using
the pressure cooker
to make it so tender,
and then everything else.
This little garnish of
the raisins is dynamite.
Excellent dish.
Lamb Shank.
Table four.
They're very tender.
And the flavor is just awesome.
Even a little zippy.
-Little zippy to it.
-Every time I eat here,
I kind of feel like
I'm eating in Matt's home.
FIERI: And he's definitely
brought a piece of home
to his restaurant.
Nora is my daughter.
My wife said, "Let's call this
Nora," and I loved it.
Chef Matt is providing
you a bite of his world.
We've got the Kofta Chalao.
Kofta Chalao --
it's not like any other meatball
you've ever had.
Kofta Chalao.
Knew that's what
he was gonna make!
[ Whispers ] I have no idea
what that meant.
[ Normal voice ] So, how do
we do it, my brother?
We take fresh ground beef,
add ground onion.
-This is Afghani meatballs?
-Yes.
Ginger. Cumin seed.
Paprika.
Coriander seed. Salt.
Red chili flake
and black pepper.
Meatball magic, coming up.
Once your oil is hot,
chopped onion.
Now the pureed garlic.
Hello, onions.
Hello, garlic.
[ Both laugh ]
We've got chopped tomatoes.
Chile de árbol.
Cilantro.
Water.
After that, we're gonna
pour the meatballs.
They sit in the sauce
raw and cook,
so they're gonna be nice
and light and fluffy.
After that, we're gonna
put our colors.
-Turmeric.
-Cumin seed.
Paprika.
Paprika. Coriander.
Sun-dried tomato.
Sweet peppers.
-Salt.
-Tomatoes. Tomato paste.
My favorite.
And some...
black licorice?
No. Plums.
Plums.
Oh, salted plums.
Yep.
Here we get some slit peas.
We've already cooked.
Yes.
And we'll cover it.
Turn the heat down.
About 20 minutes.
We're gonna serve this
with a white rice.
Basmati.
Some yogurt.
Yogurt and...?
Garlic sauce.
Put a little garnish.
Then we get some sumac.
Sumac is
this fantastic spice
that has a little lemony flavor
to it
and melts in your mouth.
♪♪
Wow. I see meatball,
and I think Italian,
but then
once you bite into this,
you go a whole different
direction in flavor.
Very fulfilling.
There's a lot going on.
The method where you
cooked them in the sauce?
You get a little bit
of that extra fat?
Delicious.
The sumac is great.
That little bit of lemon.
And there's spiciness.
Introductory-wise,
to the world of Afghan food?
That would be
one of the stars.
Kofta Chalao ready.
I'd rather eat these meatballs
than Italian meatballs.
And I'm Italian.
Don't tell my family.
[ Whispers ] Shh.
Keep it between us.
We have the Kadu
over here.
WOMAN: The flavor profiles that
he puts out of that kitchen
is second to none.
I mean, really good.
And the thing is, this helps
people to better understand
a culture they don't
know anything about.
That's true.
Nice place.
Nora should be very proud.
Thank you.
FIERI: Coming up,
we're sticking to Dallas...
That's really good.
...to hit up a Mexican place
with a passion
for the Pacific...
When you're bringing the seafood
to the big beef state,
you better have it right.
That's right.
...and taking fries
on a decadent detour.
I came here for tacos...
I'd come back
for the fritas.
♪♪
So, it's late night,
you find yourself five miles
outside of Downtown Dallas,
and you're looking
for some tacos.
Oh, there's taco trucks,
there's taco stands,
but there's only one place
that's serving up
some real-deal
Tijuana street tacos.
That's Tacos Mariachi.
Carnitas taco.
Table seven.
It reminds me of what I would
find when I would go to Mexico.
Okay.
Tacos de Lengua.
WOMAN:
I've never been to Tijuana,
and if this is what it tastes
like, I want to move there.
FIERI: But funny enough,
the taste of Tijuana
is actually cooked up
by a dude from Mexico City,
chef and owner Jesus Carmona.
Why is a guy from Mexico City
selling Tijuana street tacos?
Because I worked
in Los Cabos,
and I remember all this great
seafood from the Pacific.
Okay, we have the Pulpo.
The Pulpo Taco
is an octopus taco.
Absolutely delicious.
I love pulpo.
Let's make it, buddy!
So, first in...
we dump in the mirepoix
in the hot boiling water.
Fresh garlic. Black pepper.
Guajillo chilies.
-My favorite.
-Salt. Bay leaves and cloves.
And then massage
these beautiful pulpo.
Good.
Dip it in the water
three times.
One. Two. Three.
And the last one...
Four.
You didn't tell me
there was a four.
And the last secret,
white vinegar.
Then we let it rest
for an hour and 15 minutes.
So now we're making the
pesto sauce for our Pulpo Taco.
Parsley. Cilantro.
Fresh garlic. Serrano peppers.
Chile de árbol.
I can strip furniture
with this.
Salt.
Pepper?
Lime juice.
And lemon juice.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Turn the blender on.
Now the white vinegar
is the last step?
Yes.
And then this back on...
And voilà.
Is voilà French
or Spanish?
Well, I'm a French-Mexican.
French-Mexican. Got it.
It's not as hot as I thought
it was gonna be,
but it is really good.
You could cook your shoe
in that good.
So, let's put it on!
All right!
Now we get the pulpo.
All right,
so we chop this up.
You want to sear the octopus
in extra virgin olive oil.
A little pepper.
Needs a little salt.
And...
The pesto.
The pesto salsa.
All right.
And then bring tortillas
off the flattop.
With melted asadero cheese.
Asadero cheese.
Sliced avocado.
And then we throw
in the pulpo.
And a little bit
of the pesto.
The best way to prep
the pulpo is with this salsa.
The tomatillo.
So a nice little bit of acid.
♪♪
Mmm.
There's something
about pulpo -- so lean.
So, I'm having
a little bit of fat
come through
with the avocado
and come through
with the cheese.
It's beautiful. The way you
cooked the octopus,
it's super tender.
♪♪
The pesto. That's what kicks
it over the top.
When you're bringing the seafood
to the big beef state,
you better have it right.
That's right.
Well done, brother.
Well done.
Thank you.
Hey, how are you?
We have two Pulpo. Enjoy.
It's done exceptionally well.
It's tender.
It's not something
you would usually have,
especially here in Dallas.
FIERI: Or Trinity Groves
to be exact,
which is an up-and-coming
neighborhood
just outside of Downtown.
This area is growing.
So as the area grows, I'm gonna
keep growing the hours.
And how late are you open?
To 9:00 p.m.
And Sunday, we do the most
amazing, killer brunch.
WOMAN: All of the ingredients
are so fresh --
the tortillas,
the mole sauce.
Mole Fries. Table 11.
Pickup.
The Mole Fries? It's topped
with a special mole sauce
with crema and cheese.
I love mole. I grew up
eating it all the time
but had never thought
to have it on French fries.
When I was in Puebla,
in Mexico,
they had this guy selling potato
chips with house-made mole.
So why not tweak it a little bit
and put my own version of that?
All right, let's get
into the mole.
So, we've got guajillo.
Pasilla. Ancho chilies.
Roasted peanuts.
Sesame seeds.
We're gonna toast it?
Yes.
In the oven
for five minutes.
350 degrees.
Yes.
Then we need to add
extra virgin olive oil.
The Roma tomatoes.
White onions. Fresh garlic.
Little salt and pepper?
Then we're
gonna sauté this.
So now all the chilies
have roasted.
It's time to put them
in the hot water.
This is
a special chocolate.
The chocolate abuelita.
So it's Mexican chocolate.
It's got a little bit
of cinnamon in there,
it's got a little cumin --
It's not just like, "Hey,
I'm just throwing
in a chocolate bar."
-Oregano.
-Black pepper?
Cloves.
Chicken base.
Now we throw in the peanuts
and the toasted seeds.
Then we let it simmer
for 10 to 15 minutes.
This is cooked down?
Let's do it!
We're gonna throw
all this to the blender.
With the tomatoes and
the garlic and the onions?
Yes.
Just throw in everything.
We'll strain part of that.
To make sure we get rid
of all the solids.
Then we'll cook it
on the stove for 45 minutes?
So now we're making
the Mole Fries.
We pull them out.
Little salt.
Season it.
Put it in my basket.
My mole.
Crema fresca.
Mexican sour cream.
And fresh Cotija cheese.
And voilà.
♪♪
Mmm.
It's kind of a quick mole,
but a really good one.
'Cause you gave me
the key ingredients,
the chocolate,
the variety of the chilies...
Uh-huh.
...a little garlic,
a little tomato.
I'm telling you what, buddy.
I came here for tacos...
I'd come back
for the fritas.
Huh?
Thank you.
All right.
I have the Mole Fries.
I love these fries because
the mole has a lot of flavors.
It reminds me of
when I was younger,
which makes Tacos Mariachi
one of the most authentic
Tijuana-style restaurants
that we have here
in the city of Dallas.
This has got the attitude,
the energy...
and the flavor?
Sabor?
Muchas gracias.
De nada, de nada.
Thank you.
The jefe.
So that wraps this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
Is it me?
Hang on.
[ Pots rattle ]
I love the music
you have in the place.