Hey, everybody!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, no!
...we're reeling in some
off-the-hook seafood...
That works.
...to diving into
some stacked-up gems...
How many can I fit
in my pocket?
...like chips and a dip
in Seattle...
Now you're cooking
with gas.
...a local treasure
in Hawaii...
That ain't
your first rodeo.
...and in San Francisco...
I'm learning all the secrets
and all the tricks.
...a Chinese emporium
pulling out all the stops.
Hurry up
before I eat it all.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
♪♪
I think this has probably
happened to everybody.
You go on vacation,
you love the place so much.
On the flight home, you say,
"You know what?
We're gonna pack
all our stuff.
We're gonna move back there."
That's exactly what happened
to a couple from San Francisco.
They packed up their stuff,
moved back to Old Kainaliu
on the Big Island of Hawaii.
They are, and this is,
the Rebel Kitchen.
♪♪
Rebel burger up.
When you come to Hawaii,
this is the spot you want to be.
-Awesome.
-Ono down.
This is where a lot
of the locals come.
Oh, yeah.
It's my second kitchen.
Lomo saltado up.
There's a mix of cultures
in his menu.
I like to call it
international soul food.
FIERI: Or a mash-up
of Randy Martin's
favorite flavors,
which he and his wife,
Gabby Bermudez, are serving up
while living
their Hawaiian fantasy.
FIERI:
And "rebel" came from?
Being a rebel for our dreams
instead of being content
and just sitting
in an office
or working
for somebody else.
Amen!
Pulled pork going down.
Rebel Kitchen has a good twist
on the local favorites.
FIERI: Case in point...
Poke burger up.
-Poke burger.
Everybody on the island
is making poke,
raw fish of some sort,
but you're gonna
make it into a burger?
-Yes, sir.
-Get down with it.
All right.
First, we take our tuna.
Cubed-up fresh ahi.
We add sesame oil,
white wine vinegar,
salt, onion powder...
-Okay.
-...garlic powder...
-Raining.
-...wasabi powder.
A lot of that, huh?
Whoa.
Oh, yeah.
Shoyu and some panko,
just to bind it.
Then we're gonna add
some fresh yellow onion
and green onion.
-Okay.
-Let this sit for 2 hours.
It's gonna soak up
all the shoyu, so...
-What are we making next?
-Kona ketchup.
This is for what?
The French fries
for the burger.
French fries
First, we have tomato puree,
Italian seasoning,
garlic powder, onion power,
curry and salt, mustard...
A lot of it.
-...simple syrup...
-Whoa!
...vinegar and sugar.
Um, be right back.
All right.
How's that working
for you?
Tell me when you're done.
Let's make it happen,
captain.
All right.
House-made bun.
-Making your own bread.
-Yes, sir.
-You are a rebel.
So we're gonna take
our poke patty.
Okay.
Pan-sear it real quick
just to get a little crisp.
We're not gonna
cook it through?
No, still be raw
in the middle.
Onto the bun, avocado.
Wasabi aioli, furikake,
and a little bit
of our coleslaw mix.
Kona ketchup
for your fries.
♪♪
The curry Kona ketchup
should be outlawed.
Awesome.
Oh, that works.
That works.
That's not
a tuna fish sandwich.
That's raw poke,
held together
with a little sear
with that little bit of crunch.
You get that little touch
of that warmth to it
with a nice, hardy bun.
That's doing it right,
buddy.
Thank you very much.
-One ahi poke burger.
-I love it.
It's spicy, wonderful.
It's fantastic.
How about yourself over there,
big bite?
Mm.
I really like this place.
It's a different place.
It's like a really good
fine-dining restaurant,
but it's a hole in the wall.
You got the street noise.
When I think
of a locals' joint,
I mean, this is
right on the road.
They run a great restaurant
here with great food.
Randy is really good about
doing an infusion of spices.
FIERI: And his curry is a good
canvas for that.
I got your coconut curry
ono and shrimp.
The coconut curry,
it was an excellent dish.
The ono, which is
the wahoo fish, is really good,
and the shrimp inside of that,
very, very flavorful.
You're gonna make
your own coconut curry?
Yep, our own coconut
curry sauce.
I dig it.
let's see it.
First, we're gonna sweat
these veggies, red onion,
green onion, yellow onion,
mini sweet pepper, garlic...
Garlic.
...Thai mix, which is red
cabbage, carrot and celery.
cilantro and three
huge ghost peppers.
Let it sweat.
We're gonna add
our coconut milk, our Thai
seasoning, curry powder.
Wow, bro, you can already smell
that going on.
Oh, yeah.
Hit that with the immersion
blender and let it reduce?
Just like that.
Then, we take our ono.
We'll put it in our pan.
You know what that fish said
when it got caught, right?
-Huh?
-"Oh, no!"
-Throw in our shrimp.
-Garlic.
Mini peppers,
green onion,
a little bit of Thai mix.
Okay.
I still want my veggies
to be a little crunchy.
That curry is dangerous.
Bed of rice,
put your ono on top.
[ Whistles ]
A little bit of green onion,
some tomato,
a little bit of
Thai spice blend.
That's it.
♪♪
Oh.
That ain't
your first rodeo.
Shrimp are cooked right.
They're spot on.
The rice is really good.
The curry is dynamite.
You didn't overcook the seafood.
There's a little bit of heat
in that curry.
Oh, yeah.
I love that you left
the veggies crunchy,
especially when you're doing
this kind of a dish
with nice, fresh fish.
♪♪
It's an honest dish.
Well done, my friend.
-Thank you very much.
-Well done.
Coconut curry up.
It's delicious,
a nice, flaky fish.
It's got just enough spice
to kind of kick you in the mouth
but not overwhelming.
In the network of all
the locals,
everybody knows
about Rebel Kitchen.
Yes, they do, and they know
that it's special
and different.
The flavors blend together
like the people here in Hawaii.
FIERI: When people come
to the Big Island,
this is the kind of place
that they want from "Triple D,"
like, "Come on, Guy,
take us to that funky,
hole-in-the-wall joint,"
and you will find the rebels
in the community,
and you're one of them.
-Thank you very much.
-Congrats.
FIERI:
Up next, in San Francisco...
Dude, I'm impressed.
...a Chinese joint
putting out the surf...
Take this
$6 million lobster.
...turf...
Every bite
is just luxurious.
...and dim sum running wild.
-Watch out, Guy.
-Whoa.
♪♪
So I'm here in south
San Francisco,
about 10 minutes
from SFO Airport.
We're about to check out
one of the biggest "Triple D"
joints ever --
seating over
450 people at a time.
Oh, yes, the dim sum
is fantastic,
but we're here because it's
owned by one of our favorite
"Triple D" chefs,
Benny Lin and his brother.
This is Grand Harbor.
Dim fish coming up!
Nice ingredients, good flavors.
It's amazing.
This place is both the dim sum
place and a seafood restaurant.
FIERI:
Brought together by Benny Lin,
who we first met at Pagoda,
his Alaska spot where
he's serving up Asian fusion.
How different is Pagoda
to Grand Harbor?
Grand Harbor is 100%
traditional Chinese.
And few things are more
classic than dim sum.
Hello.
Dim sum is appetizer-size,
almost like Chinese tapas.
LIN: You just see everything
on the cart,
and you say, "I want Shaomai.
I want sticky rice."
FIERI: It's like
a traveling buffet.
Exactly.
You definitely get
a lot of variety.
I am the kind of person
that always wants to steal food
from my neighbor's plate.
FIERI:
And who wouldn't want to pilfer
a fist full of pork?
-Pork buns!
MAN: The pork buns
are very good here.
They're on the sweet side.
I like the barbecue pork inside.
First, we're gonna make
the dough for the pork bun.
All right, let's go.
Flour, eggs,
condensed milk...
-Sugar.
-...sugar.
And then we add the water.
All right.
We're gonna mix
these together for 15 minutes,
and we set up for,
like, 3 or 4 hours.
Next step...
Make the sauce for
the barbecue pork...
...salt,
and food coloring.
To give it a little bit
of that red.
A little red.
There's something about
a little bit of that color.
Yes,
and we mix the sauce.
How long are we going
to let it marinade?
-Like, 15, 20 minutes.
-Okay.
We just hang it
in the barbecue oven.
-Roasted for 45 minutes at 425?
-Yes, sir.
And then we'll bring it out,
chop that up.
The flavor is dynamite.
-Thank you.
Why can't I just have
a bowl of that?
-You can get it.
-Anything you want, Benny says.
Anything you want.
There's nothing
that Benny won't do, can't do.
We're gonna make the sauce
for the barbecue.
-Hurry up before I eat it all.
-Okay.
...sugar, salt,
black pepper.
And then
drop in the pork?
Mix these together
for the filling for the bun.
Okay.
Okay, we're gonna do
the dough right now,
so we make
the dough like this.
Okay, so now we fill it?
Got it.
Fill that like this,
then we just roll these up.
Okay, so how long is this
gonna proof now?
-15 minutes.
-How many of these a day?
-200 to 300.
-Yes.
-That's a lot of work.
That's what makes the sheen
on the outside.
-Yes.
-Huh.
I'm learning all the secrets
and all the tricks.
You got it today.
We cook it in the oven
at 425 for...
15 minutes.
♪♪
All right.
[ Sniffs ]
Ahh.
You can smell the yeast.
How many of these
can you eat?
I can eat 15.
-I could 15, too.
-All right.
We must challenge this
today, all right?
No, let's not challenge
it today
because I want to eat one
dim sum from every basket.
Good.
♪♪
That is so good.
When you break into it,
and you get
a good amount of filling,
this has that nice,
sweet glaze on top,
one from the dough and two
from the mayo
and the condensed milk...
-Uh-huh.
Then you get inside,
the roasted pork,
little bit of salt,
little bit of sugar,
every bite is just luxurious.
How many can I fit
in my pocket?
♪♪
The pork is extremely tender,
nice sauce mixture there.
It melts in your mouth.
The bread itself is sweet,
so you get a little bit
of crisp on the top.
WOMAN: Egg custard.
I've never been in a dim
sum restaurant like this.
MAN #2: This place has a little
bit of everything.
You have a great view.
It's actually one of
the best views in the Bay.
We're hanging out at
Grand Harbor in San Francisco,
just south of the airport.
When we come back, you're
going to see something
you've never seen on
"Triple D" before, chicken feet.
See you in a bit.
All right.
You get those six.
I get these six.
Let's go.
♪♪
So welcome back.
We're hanging out
at Grand Harbor.
"Triple D" is in
south San Francisco,
hanging out
with Benny Lin.
Beef and tenderloin right now.
And I got to tell you,
this is dim sum heaven.
MAN #3: The dim sum menu here
is extensive,
much more than
a normal dim sum place
that you go around
the Bay area.
Now, we've seen pig's feet
on the show, snout.
You've seen head cheese.
You've seen some funky things.
Today, first time...
Chicken feet.
-Chicken feet.
-I love the chicken feet.
It's got some really
succulent meat in there.
It just makes it a really
nice and tasty treat.
You know I trust Benny
if we're gonna have
chicken feet. All right.
LIN: A little bit of vinegar,
sugar...
This is real-deal
chicken feet.
They've cleaned them,
cut off the claw.
Put them
in the hot water.
So we boil them 10 or 15
minutes, then we fry them.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
You're gonna throw wet
chicken feet in 500-degree oil.
♪♪
Watch out, Guy.
Whoa.
All right.
So now we fry them.
Around 8 to 10 minutes.
Then we're gonna boil them
again, this time for an hour.
Yes, so all the meat
and skin get soft.
Now we're gonna make
the sauce.
Then it gets mixed in.
Oyster sauce, soy sauce,
chicken base,
salt, sugar,
cornstarch,
food coloring...
Got it.
...so we're gonna mix
these up right here.
We just dump
all the chicken feet in
and mix
everything together.
-And this is a specialty?
-Yep, it is.
Jalapeños and some fresnos,
okay.
Yep.
Cover up.
Steam it
for 15 minutes.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay, I'll be waiting.
Okay.
Ready?
♪♪
The flavor is killer.
It's super tender.
It's so good.
You get all the skin, the fat,
the little bit of meat.
It's creamy.
Just forget that
it's a chicken foot.
Dude, I'm impressed.
-Thank you.
This is your chicken feet.
MAN #4: The texture is not what
you would expect,
a little sauce, really tasty.
So I'm sitting here
with two of my favorite
"Triple D" chefs,
the one and only Gorilla,
so down in Pacifica,
Gorilla Barbecue.
These guys
were all telling me,
"You've got to come down
to see Grand Harbor."
Tell me what makes this
so much different.
Benny Lin,
now that I've had this,
I can't wait to go try
some more stuff.
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
There's so much variety,
and, you know, it's great
to try something new every time.
You can always order dishes like
prawns with walnuts and lobster.
Steamed lobster.
The lobster with the garlic
sauce is very tasty.
Its like butter, basically.
So we're gonna do a lobster
in garlic sauce.
Okay, and we break
the lobster down.
And we're gonna do
this way.
We're putting the lobster
back together, folks.
Take this
$6 million lobster,
we can rebuild him bigger,
faster, stronger than before.
We're gonna
just add garlic.
-Fresh garlic.
-Garlic oil.
Put in the steamer
for 5 to 6 minutes.
-All right.
-There we go.
Green onions,
hot vegetable oil,
some soy sauce.
FIERI: And what does this
normally get served with?
White rice on the side,
or you can just eat it
like that.
The thing that I love about this
is that you steamed it.
All the flavor of the lobster
stay here.
Yep, stay here.
Yep.
You got a little bit of oil,
a little bit of soy sauce,
so you get to taste the lobster,
and it's nice and tender.
I see why hundreds and hundreds
of people come here.
Thank you.
This is
the steamed lobster.
Very tasty,
love the garlic in it.
The lobster is perfectly cooked,
hit the spot.
They sell that and dim sum here.
-Delicious.
-Thank you.
I was expecting an 8.
I got a 12.
Thank you.
-World class, Benny.
-Thank you.
FIERI: Coming up,
a Seattle brewhouse...
I'm being hypnotized.
...dishing out
a pub-grub classic...
That's flaky goodness,
right there.
...and a bite of beef
good till the last drop.
Look, squirrel!
No, no, no, no,
not that one.
No, no, no, no, not that...
Benny, not that one.
We'll be here all week.
♪♪
I'm here at the Great Wall
of China.
Oh, no, actually
I'm in Seattle, Washington,
in the Fremont neighborhood
and here to check out
a restaurant
that's in a building
that's been moved twice,
but what stayed the same
was the fact
that they've got
an old-school pub menu,
and they're serving
local craft beers.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the Red Door.
♪♪
Boss Hog coming up.
This is a place everybody knows.
It's a place everybody goes.
Hey, guys, how are those
beers tasting?
It's the staff, as well as the
food and beer, it's fantastic.
Beef dip and tots.
I've been coming here
for 25 years.
FIERI: That's recent history
for this turn-of-the-century
building
that began as a drugstore
and turned into a tavern
by the time Peter and
Emily Hanning came on board.
We've really maintained
just pouring quality beers.
-What's the menu?
-Things that go well with beer.
FIERI: Or are made with it,
courtesy of Chef Chris Gauntz.
EMILY:
Your fish and chips.
The fish and chips
is delectable.
They have the beer batter.
It's a staple here
at the Red Door.
So we're gonna make our beer
batter for our fish and chips.
The beer really does give it
that extra little flavor.
You can taste the hops in there.
-Okay.
So first, we're gonna add
our two pitches
of a local pale ale.
-Fish and chips is big here?
-It is.
It is one of our
biggest sellers.
And we've got a little
granulated onion
and granulated garlic,
salt, black pepper,
baking powder...
-There you go.
-...cayenne...
-A good amount.
-...some Old Bay.
-A whole mess of cornstarch.
-Give it a little mix.
We're gonna add egg,
a bunch of flour,
and whisk it down
until we get
the consistency we want.
You must have
a big right arm.
Now we're gonna cut down
some of our
Alaskan wild-cut cod.
-There's no Seattle cod?
-There probably is.
I thought I "cod" some
last time I was up here.
So smaller, thin slices.
Dredge in the flour,
into our beer batter
we just made.
I like the amount of pepper
in there.
-Straight to the fryer.
-Next step?
-Our house-made tartar sauce.
-Okay.
A nice amount of mayonnaise here
to start with,
some dill relish...
-That's a big dill.
...some pureed-down
onions and celery...
I like that move.
...salt, black pepper,
a little bit of lemon
juice and dried parley...
Here it comes.
...hot sauce, and we're
gonna whisk it up.
There's our tartar.
So now that we got it
all fried up,
get it set up for presentation,
fresh coleslaw,
seasoned hand-cut fries
and then our cod,
and we are good to go.
Enjoy.
That's flaky goodness
right there.
That's actually, like,
the perfect bite.
Mm.
But see, that's
the ratio you want.
I want
the right amount of fish
to the right amount
of batter.
It doesn't take
a lot of time
to get that size
fish cooked,
so it doesn't soak up
a lot of oil.
This is tender,
falls apart.
It's not fishy.
I do get a little bit
of that beer.
And when you don't need
the tartar sauce,
then you're winning.
The fish stands on its own.
Well, it actually can't,
because it...
Has no legs.
-Exactly.
-Technicalities.
That's what
always gets you.
That's good
fish and chips.
Well done.
EMILY: All right.
Here's your fish and chips.
Crunchy and flaky, and
the beer batter is perfection.
I actually love the tartar
sauce. It got some kick.
Fire Circle, J-4.
The Red Door is a slice
of old Seattle.
Everyone comes here.
We see the same people
every time we come.
FIERI: Even I'm running
into folks I know.
This woman right here,
Voula,
the first time
we ever shot in Seattle,
we shot a funky little place
called Voula's
Offshore Cafe.
We meet the two crazy sons,
Niko and Sikey,
so you find a place
like the Red Door,
and it's nice to see
these mom-and-pop places
that are making real food,
lots of community.
Very tasty stuff.
Order up.
MAN #5: They have a wonderful
variety of food.
You can come here for the wings.
You can come here for the tots,
so you can come here
for a full burger.
FIERI: Or take it
to the next level
with the prime rib classic.
GAUNTZ:
Beef dip to the window.
The beef dip has
a fantastic sauce.
The beef is always tender.
One of my favorites on the menu.
We're gonna make our beef
dip sandwich next.
Let's see it.
So we start off with a nice,
big prime rib.
No bone, there is
a good amount of fat.
Hit it with some stout beer
and water.
Now we're gonna make our rub,
a little salt,
black pepper, rosemary, thyme,
a little granulated onion...
-Okay.
-...fresh minced garlic.
We're gonna mix it up
and rub it down.
Now how long are we going
to roast this off?
For about 45 minutes.
Put a nice sear on it
and give it a nice crust.
And then we'll be pulling it
out of the oven,
wrapping it tightly and
putting it in the slow cooker
for about 4 more hours.
-Low and slow...
And then we're gonna
cool it down, thin-slice it,
portion it out
to about a 5-ounce portion.
And you're re-heating
that in jus?
Correct.
Fortify the au jus with garlic,
black pepper, veggie base.
-Okay.
Put it on the line for service.
All right.
Now we're gonna make
our horseradish aioli.
Got to have a little fat
on that.
"More fat, more flavor,"
they say.
All right.
So there's lemon juice,
minced garlic...
-This is my kind of aioli.
...Dijon mustard, salt.
Prepared horseradish,
got it.
...a couple eggs, then we're
gonna get them going.
We're gonna add the oil.
Slow pour is critical
for the emulsification.
I'm being hypnotized.
And then we're gonna add
a little water.
We can get the consistency
where we want it,
and we got our horseradish
aioli ready to go.
Mm, nice little tang,
good amount of garlic.
Let's make
that sandwich, homes.
Go from the jus
onto the flattop...
Cover it with cheese.
Let that cheese melt,
horseradish aioli.
I like it.
We got our sandwich
all finished up.
Get it nice and toasty,
the au jus we just made...
...finishing up
with a little tots.
Not shy
on the tots, are we?
And we're good to go.
I think what I really like
about it
is its bread/meat ratio.
The jus has got a good
little tang to it,
good crust on the bread.
The bread is actually
super critical
because it's got to be able
to really soak it up.
I want that big,
wet bite.
You don't want it
falling apart on you
after it soaks it up,
either.
That is the key.
Look, squirrel!
♪♪
Chef, nicely done, huh?
EMILY:
And the beef dip with tots.
The beef dip is incredible,
and when you dip into the sauce,
it's perfect.
This is Mandy.
She is one of our lead cameras
on "Triple G,"
and her friend, Keith.
What do you think of the dip?
I love the dip and the fact
that they toasted the bread.
People don't give
the bread enough love,
and these guys are doing it?
-Yes.
Tavern burger, to the window.
It's our home away from home.
You do what people like,
give them the consistency,
take care of business.
Well done, my friend.
-Thank you.
Watch out for that guy.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I'm here at the Great Wall
of China.
Actually, I got to be honest,
I'm here in
Seattle, Washington, in the...
That was good.
If this is some sick way
to make me exercise,
I'm really not happy with it.