Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun --
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
This trip...
Wha-wha-wha!
...it's a full hour of
primetime pork.
Hello, Flavortown? Yeah,
my pig meter's goin' off.
From California
to Carolina...
Delicious.
...Buffalo to Phoenix...
That's it -- we've hit
the destination, we're here.
...we've got
off-the-chain chops...
You'll dig that.
...meaty Italian...
I can't wait.
...masterful Mexican...
Mmm! Oh, yeah.
...and old-school gems.
Fried bologna and onions,
you had me there.
Plus, we're smokin'...
Great barbecue.
...dippin'...
O...M...G.
...stackin'...
Holy ham and cheese!
...and goin' big with the pig.
You guys want to come down
and help me eat this?
That's all right here,
right now, on Triple D.
♪♪
[ Engines rumbling ]
I'm here in North Central
Phoenix, Arizona,
on Camelback Road
to check out a joint
that looks like it came from my
home turf -- the wine country --
and to meet a chef that's doing
my kind of cooking --
wood-fired.
This is St. Francis.
French onion burger up.
The food is fantastic always.
CHAMBERLIN:
Vegetable flatbread up.
Consistent good food.
It has, like, its own
unique little twists
and quirks and flavors.
FIERI: Just like the chef behind
it all -- Aaron Chamberlin.
I grew up as a Boy Scout.
I always cooked
on an open fire.
So, when he opened this joint
in '09,
he saw no reason
to do anything different.
I wanted to have
a big wood-burning oven
so I could have my little fire
going in my restaurant.
MAN: They're all masters
at what they do.
There's a lot of good stuff
on the menu.
FIERI:
Including this top seller.
Pig dip up.
Just like a French dip,
but pork style.
First thing we're gonna make
is our brine for our pork.
Water goes in.
So, bringing that up.
Second thing, star anise.
Very strong.
Fennel seed.
Bay leaf.
Toasted coriander seed.
Of course you toasted it.
Ancho chili.
We go on to
the fresh ingredients.
We got thyme there
and fresh rosemary.
Kosher salt.
You got the sugar.
Boom.
Bring this up to boil,
and we let it sit and marinate.
We have our brine,
just off the stove.
We strained all the spices
and herbs out of there.
I have some ice that I...
Oh, that's nice!
...slightly cooled down.
It's a good brine.
Mm! That star anise
is what really --
Comes through.
Yeah.
Mmm!
And we stick our pork
right in there.
Overnight -- 12 hours.
Overnight.
We put salt and pepper
on it...
and roast it
in the wood oven.
What temp
does the oven run?
The oven right now
is at 616 degrees.
Our roast is ready,
and you can see how nice
and beautiful it is.
I just come right in here.
Oh. That rack of ribs.
Yeah, you can smell that guy
right there.
Are you talking
about this guy, or...
Well, no, the pork.
Okay.
So, we have the chine
right there,
and then what we do
is we just slice nice,
little, thin pieces.
Layer our sandwich here.
Put applewood smoked bacon,
Gruyère cheese like that.
Back in the oven?
Back in the oven.
Let that melt.
We're gonna assemble
the sandwich.
Fennel-onion marmalade,
a generous amount of it.
Dijon mustard
for a little picante.
Melted cheese.
Just slide this
right off...
Oh, gosh.
...onto that.
We add prosciutto -- That's one
thing we don't cook --
and the top bun.
O...M...G.
Cut this in half.
We have our nice,
beautiful pork au jus.
Pig jus.
Put that right there.
Hello, Flavortown?
Yeah, my pig meter's going off.
Smoky, crunchy, creamy.
I haven't even dipped
this thing yet.
Now we're gonna take
this bad boy for a test drive.
That's it!
We've hit the destination!
We're here!
That's got to be
within the top five
best pork sandwiches
I've ever had,
combining that
with the top five
best dip sandwiches
I've ever had.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
WOMAN: It's delicious.
Nice, salty flavor.
The sauce
is really good.
The bread is crunchy,
but not soggy.
All the perfect things
about a sandwich.
Ohh.
One of the best dips
I've ever had.
This place definitely
stands out within Phoenix.
It's just amazing.
This is like a vacation,
and it's just down
the street from us.
You don't play
anything safe.
Everything
is touchdown bombs.
I've had
an incredible visit.
Thank you.
You got to come
meet this cat. Amazing.
So since we're all about pork,
you can't pass up
a classic cut we're grabbin'
on the East Coast.
We love coming
to North Carolina.
Every time we've come here,
we've got great food
experiences.
Now I'm about 15 miles
outside of downtown Charlotte
on Highway 2427
at an old converted
1930s gas station
where two brothers
who started out slinging
hamburgers and hot dogs
at car shows
are now serving up
some new Southern dishes
here at Jake's Good Eats.
Let me get one more of those.
Oh, yeah.
We're going boom, and then
straight into that guy.
I love this place.
BLT.
Feels almost like you're going
to a friend's house for dinner.
Bethany and Brice.
The food is phenomenal.
It's always unique.
Venison quesadilla.
FIERI:
All thanks to Jake Stegall
Double pork chop.
and his brother Gordon
Don't forget about that mac --
it's on.
who opened this place to do
their childhood favorites
their way.
We put our twist
on Southern cooking.
FIERI: And these guys
are putting in 80-hour weeks
Crab cake down...
just to get it right.
We love being in the kitchen,
we love the insanity.
FIERI: Jake's even here
a couple of days
after running his motorcycle
into a tree.
Ow, how's the tree look?
Better than me.
What are we gonna make?
Maple-glazed
double-cut pork chop
with our roasted garlic
mashed potatoes,
candied apples,
and sauteed spinach.
It's the best pork chop
I've ever had.
You're gonna give us
a true double cut?
Big boy.
Let's see it.
Get that fat off that bone
and just French these out
and here's our pork chop.
You're basically making
two chops into one.
He did it real-deal way.
I'm in it now.
We're gonna come over here,
salt and pepper both sides.
Canola oil on that
to keep 'em from sticking.
We're going right
on the grill with this?
We're going right on
the char grill.
We'll let that go
for three or four minutes,
get some marks on it.
Dynamite.
We'll take a gala apple here
and cut these into fours,
and I'm gonna core out this.
Little canola oil in the pan,
get these browning.
Okay.
Turn these guys here
and now it's time
to add brown sugar.
We just make it here,
it's our molasses
and sugar.
You make your own brown sugar?
You're darn right.
Oh, I love to see it.
A little butter in here.
You're almost gonna make
a caramel that's gonna
go around those apples.
Exactly right.
Now I'm gonna make our glaze.
Maple syrup
and a little Creole mustard.
Our chops are getting finished
over here.
Looks nice.
We're gonna glaze it
with our maple and Creole
mustard glaze here
and then finish that
in the oven.
Five minutes
so that candies up.
Add our sauteed spinach
and mashed potatoes,
candied apples,
and now our pork chop.
A little bit more glaze here
right on top of our apples,
right on top of the chop.
Mmm, delicious.
Buddy, I tell you what,
you hit that in all
the right spots.
The thing
that I'm so impressed with,
you knocked out the temperature
on point.
All the juice.
The mashed are great,
the apples,
I can still see real apple.
And the chop --
the chop's legit, man.
You'll dig that,
that's a top chop.
Here's your
maple-glazed pork chop.
Fresh pork chop
with a sweetness to it.
Cooked perfectly,
got a great flavor,
off-the-grill tasty.
Blackened flounder,
table seven.
Thank you.
I just love the food.
All right,
we're ready to roll.
We'll be back.
Always, yes.
Here's the oyster po' boy.
They treat us
like we're family.
You really do appreciate
every person that comes
through the door.
Absolutely.
Thank you.
Great experience,
congratulations.
Thank you, brother.
FIERI: Coming up,
a family-run joint
in Garden Grove,
California...
Today is my lucky day.
...servin' up the pork...
The flavor jets are
turning on.
...in their South-of-the-border
specialties.
It's delicious, chef.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Garden Grove, California,
right off the 22 freeway
on Harbor Boulevard.
I'm here to check out a joint
where I hear this Mexican family
put it all on the line to open
and own their own restaurant
and serve up
real-deal Mexican food.
This is Sabroso!
MAN: One torta.
I can't say enough
about how good everything is.
Chamorro ready to go.
Every bite is a magical bite.
It's perfect.
Really has the sazón of
the family, and you really --
The sazón.
Sazón.
The flavor of the family.
FIERI:
That would be the Muñoz family,
with veteran chef papa Tito
leading the charge.
Have you always been
this close of a family?
All the time.
We always did
a lot of things together.
Like taking the plunge
and opening this joint in 2012
with a menu
based on Mom's recipes.
WOMAN: This food is delicious,
it's fresh, it's flavorful.
You just can't go wrong
with anything.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
The tamale.
Pork tamale ready.
It's the best.
We're gonna make tamales.
I'm gonna do the pork.
Pork tamale.
So, we're gonna put in a --
Pork butt
that's been just cut up.
Cook it in the water
with some salt,
some onions,
Mexican oregano.
garlic,
and bay leaves.
And we're just gonna
cook it down?
Cook it down.
The rest of this
goes in there?
Yes.
Mexican oregano.
Okay.
Black pepper.
Black peppercorns.
Got it.
The onion.
Onions. Garlic.
Cumin.
Cumin seeds. Got it.
Allspice.
Then we're gonna put some water.
Where's my --
Well, why don't we put the water
from the peppers?
What does "Sabroso" mean?
Delicious.
Sabroso.
We're gonna add
the peppers.
That's the guajillo and...
California?
Chile de arbol.
Okay.
Now we go
to the hot oil?
Yes.
Got to strain it a little bit
'cause there's some solid.
[ Sizzling ]
This is what
you want to hear.
Oh, that sauce.
My mouth is just --
the flavor jets are turning on.
How long is that gonna cook,
chef?
20 minutes.
And then we'll be ready to take
and add it to the pork.
There you go.
So, now we have the masa.
Yes.
Gonna put the salt.
Little baking soda.
Yes.
To puff it a little bit.
Add some more shortening.
Now we're gonna put
the pork stock into the masa.
Then we're gonna start
mixing it up all together.
So, I got the pork.
Mmm!
Oh, yeah.
Sabroso.
Skins.
The masa.
Okay.
You soften them in the water
so they're pliable.
There you go.
Okay.
Over?
Just roll it.
There you go.
You know
how to make tamales.
I've made a few tamales
in my day.
This is a tamale pot.
See how that sits above
the water as they cook?
All right, chef.
We ready?
Whoa!
Look at that.
They're delicious.
The masa has great texture.
The pork is delicious.
Not too spicy.
And you got a good ratio.
It's not a bunch of masa
and a little bit of pork inside.
This is like a nice
50/50.
Just the right amount of sauce.
WOMAN:
Hot but not too hot.
It leaves a nice little bite
in your mouth.
WOMAN: Everything you order
is gonna be good,
so it's really fun
to try different things.
Chamorro plate.
It's hot.
This is the Chamorro plate.
It's super yummy.
It has meat
with the red sauce.
It's magical.
Chamorro.
Yeah.
What does it mean
in English?
The shank.
That's the shank?
Uh-huh.
Big shank.
Go ahead. Get me started.
Okay.
We're gonna salt it first.
So,
I have to sear them.
FIERI: Oh, we're gonna
sear them off on the flattop.
Yeah.
While those are searing?
We're gonna make the salsa
for the Chamorro.
We have all the ingredients
over here.
We have cloves,
bay leaves.
Some coriander.
Mexican oregano.
Cumin.
Cumin seeds. Got it.
Allspice.
Peppercorn.
Garlic.
Onions.
And then ginger.
Ginger? Come on.
In Mexico?
That one is mine.
[ Laughs ]
I have to find something --
I'm gonna tell your mom.
He changed the recipe.
[ Chuckles ]
So then we're gonna put
some of the --
Super spicy
with the chili de arbol.
We got kind of spicy and smokey
with the guajillo,
and pretty mild
with the California.
Some water.
Okay.
Put the lid.
Gonna drop them in the pot
with a little bit of water,
and this is when we're
gonna cook them low and slow.
Hang on a second.
I want to taste that.
Oh, it's good
except the ginger.
I'm kidding.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're gonna cook all
the mixture off a little bit.
Right.
Once it's done,
we put the sauce on there,
and then this all goes
for an hour and a half.
All together. Yeah.
We're gonna put
some peppers.
Which peppers are these?
California and guajillo
and the arbol.
So now we're gonna put
the salt.
We're gonna cover it?
Yeah,
we're gonna cover now.
This is the Peruano beans.
Herano?
Peruano.
We have the Chamorro
ready here.
We just put some pico de gallo
in the middle.
Queso fresco.
It's delicious, Chef.
It's got great texture,
not too spicy.
This has a lot of depth.
Not over seasoned.
The meat's super tender.
Today is my lucky day.
I followed the rainbow.
You're my pot of gold.
Chamorro ready to go.
It is absolutely amazing.
MAN:
It's really tasty.
I love a little kick without it
overpowering everything else.
It's just good food, honestly.
Everybody comes in happy,
leaves stuffed and more happy.
The food and the service and
the family energy is outrageous.
It's been an awesome experience.
Very proud of you.
FIERI: Up next,
a musical chef in Phoenix...
Mm. Wow.
...singin' a different tune
with an Italian staple.
You're just playin'
your masterpiece
on the canvas of the plate.
In Charleston,
South Carolina...
Show-off.
...a dynamite diner
that knows how to top a chop.
Dude, that's ridiculous.
My great-grandfather's name
was Giuseppe Fieri,
and of course,
I love Italian food.
Now I'm down here
in Phoenix, Arizona,
where most people
would expect,
well, Southwestern
or Mexican food.
So you know I gotta
jump at the shot
to try some old-school
Italian cooking,
here at Giuseppe's on 28th.
Hey, Cindy, I got you
a bolognese. Here it is.
Authentic Italian.
He's got the fresh pasta.
It's divine.
Absolutely spectacular.
That's wha-wha-wha!
Here you go, darlin'.
What is it about
this place?
Number one -- the food,
and number two --
the wait staff and Rich.
What's the matter, you?
He's a kick.
FIERI: He is owner Rich Bock...
Cheers, guys.
An Italian food fanatic...
Shrimp raviata.
And a world-class musician...
BOCK: I ended up playing
professionally in New York,
got a chance
to go to Italy.
FIERI: And landed a gig
in Florence.
I was there
nine years and change.
The food thing there is --
you know, it's everybody's hobby
and passion.
Everybody's everything.
Everything.
Beautiful.
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
FIERI: So when he came
back to the States,
he brought
the recipes with him
and got this place rolling.
He knows how to make food
the way my mother makes it.
Let's put some pasta
in there.
You just wouldn't
expect something
this good, this authentic
in a strip mall.
The shrimp ravioli.
FIERI: In a little joint
with only 12 tables.
We got about
1,000 square feet,
and about 600 of it
is probably the kitchen.
I was gonna say -- 60/40.
It's quaint, it's fun.
The food's great.
When I have the time, I try
to do something that I haven't
been doing -- a different
dessert or a different dish.
FIERI: Like osso buco
done three ways...
Osso buco ready.
FIERI: Classic veal or beef...
Ossa buco for you.
...or the fan favorite here...
These are pork shanks.
Pork shanks out of it.
I tried the pork,
and people are loving it.
Just a little salt,
and I'm gonna add pepper.
Wow you're very gentle
with the seasoning on that.
Well, there's a lot
going on here.
Right, so now we're gonna
lightly flour these.
Just on the ends, huh?
Yeah. Hot pan.
All right, you put a little
sear on the top and the bottom.
About three, four
minutes on a side.
Okay, the little crust.
All right, I'm down
with where we are.
Put some more oil in the pan.
Gonna sauté my vegetables.
Yeah, I love the red onion.
Did you see that getting used
predominantly in Italy?
In Florence where I was --
only red onion.
Carrots, celery.
A little salt and pepper.
Celery.
Throw in some garlic,
my favorite -- rosemary
and thyme -- I just love that.
I give it a stir.
I'm just gonna put
a little bit down on the bottom.
Now I'm just gonna put
the osso buco on top.
I'm gonna put the rest
of the vegetables in,
just everywhere.
It's like garden madness.
It is.
A little tomato sauce?
A little tomato sauce.
So far, so great.
A little wine.
Oh. 375 degrees
for how long?
Two and a half hours.
I can't wait.
Nuggets of happiness.
I can just touch it
and just see it's falling --
pan's hot.
Came out of the oven.
Oh.
Okay, so now we're gonna make
the pasta that complements this?
Yes.
A little oil, a little lemon,
a little parsley.
We put the pasta in,
give this a toss.
Oh, that fresh pasta
just rocks.
Look at that.
Beautiful drippings.
Look at the way it just pulls
right away from that bone.
Anytime you can cook the meat
next to that big of a bone,
the flavor's gotta be
just intense.
Yeah.
Mmm. Wow.
That's so super flavor.
Oh, man.
I never had it
with pork shanks before.
No?
Wow, what a treat, and a little
bit of the mirepoix --
the carrots and the celery --
really nice. Delicious.
Boy, you sure brought
some gems back from Italy.
Yeah.
It's just delicious.
It is always really good.
Cindy, table four.
Always just really nice
coming back here.
We know we're gonna get
a good meal,
and we're gonna
enjoy ourselves.
ALL: Chin chin.
It's a total dream.
I love the clientele.
So much fun
and satisfying.
I think that's
the musician in you.
This time you're just
playing your masterpiece
on the canvas
of the plate.
Thank you.
Wow.
I'm out on that.
FIERI: Now we're going
from Italian to digging in
to some Southern.
So I'm here
in Charleston, South Carolina,
on the very busy
Savannah highway
just a few miles out of downtown
to check out a joint
where a couple has been working
for years
to put this diner together.
They got it all completed.
All they needed to do was
come up with a name.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, and did they have
some doozies. Let's see.
They had "The Rusty Bucket,"
"The American U.S.A. Diner,"
or my personal favorite,
"Dexter's House of Gravy."
well, they finally figured out
what they're gonna name it,
and here it is --
the Early Bird Diner.
Order up. Open faced turkey.
Southern comfort food.
Bowl o'grits.
MAN: I think I probably eat here
almost more than I eat at home.
I'm normally here
early in the morning
and late at night.
FIERI:
And this dude's got company.
We come to the Early Bird Diner
usually around 2:00 or 3:00
in the morning,
not necessarily for breakfast.
FIERI: That's right.
Since '08,
owners Dexter Haigler...
Order up. Shrimp and grits.
...and Nicole Morris...
Chicken & waffles.
...have been keeping
their fryer frying late...
[ Chuckles ] and I mean late.
Biscuits and gravy bacon.
Friday and Saturday,
we go 8:00 a.m.
till 4:00 in the morning.
Eventually, I think
we do want to do 24 hours.
We're building towards that.
That's called crazy.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, right?
You know, we wanted to have
a place where we could do
whatever we want.
We're just trying to make
simple food really well.
FIERI: Here "simple" means
this scratch-made top seller.
Fried pork chop.
Thank you.
That looks good.
WOMAN: The pork chop is so good.
I love the sweet and spicy jelly
with it.
I get it on everything that
I get here at the diner.
[ Laughs ]
What are we making?
Uh, pepper jelly
for the pork chop.
And what do we get
the pectin out of?
It comes from apples.
When we talk about jelly,
what's gonna jellify it --
so this is actually apple?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's made from apples.
Apple. Good. Cool.
Start with
our, uh, pineapple juice,
pepper vinegar.
Pepper vinegar?
We take apple cider vinegar.
We chop up, uh, hot chilies
and put it in there.
Over time, it gets
spicier and spicier.
Show-off.
Sugar,
fire-roasted bell peppers.
Now I'm gonna puree
the peppers.
[ Whirs ]
I'm gonna add my pectin.
There we go.
So stir that in.
Now I'm gonna add
my frozen peppers.
These are gonna be what are
gonna actually cool this down?
Yeah.
Looks like
a bunch of bell peppers --
red, yellow.
And, uh, a little bit
of jalapeño.
This should give us
a nice, spicy red pepper jelly.
Mm-hmm.
It's gotta cool overnight.
All right. This is, uh, this is
what my pork chops look like
when they get here.
The chine bone has not been
taken out?
No. I actually like
the extra bone on there
'cause we make
our own pork stock.
So if you're gonna buy it,
buy it with the bone
because the flavor's
in the bone.
You won't see that
every day.
All right.
You're gonna pound this down,
tenderize it up.
Sorry. [ Laughs ]
Now the dredge?
Yes, sir.
Got A.P. flour,
a little bit of blackening,
a little fresh ground black,
and a little kosher salt.
So we're gonna flour,
buttermilk, flour.
Then it's in the fryer.
Canola oil at 350?
Yes, sir.
Right on.
Pork chop's ready.
Pork chop maximus.
Finish this up with
our fire-roasted pepper jelly,
and that's
with a little mac and cheese
and some
fresh collard greens there.
I need to get
some pepper jelly to go, man.
Look at that.
[ Utensils clink ]
[ Mouth full ]
It's real simple.
The chop is not over-seasoned,
not over-fried, not greasy.
You get a little bit
of that crunch.
With that pepper jelly,
real pepper flavor,
dude, that is ridiculous.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Fried chop.
Got pepper jelly right here.
Order up. Fried pork chop.
Well, what did you have?
Oh, the, uh,
fried pork chop.
How was it?
It's mostly gone,
but delicious.
You got this great crunch
in the crust,
but the pork chop is
still moist,
and the pepper jelly gives it
just a little bit
of sweet, spicy kick to it
right at the end.
Chicken & waffles.
Oh.
Shrimp and grits.
Early bird in one word --
satisfying.
It is probably one of the most
satisfying meals I've had.
FIERI: Fun place.
I like the attitude.
I like the energy.
Thanks for having me, guys.
It was fun.
Yeah, thanks
for being here, man.
Appreciate it. Thanks.
Really appreciate it.
FIERI: Coming up on this
hour-long pork-a-palooza...
Oh! Did you see that?
...we're hittin'
the bomb bologna in Buffalo.
That's awesome.
And in Atlanta...
Hut!
...a throwback joint gone wild.
What do you think?
You know, one of the things
we dig on Triple "D"
is stories about restaurants
being passed down
from generation to generation.
A lot of times,
it's father to son,
but every once in while,
we get one with a little twist,
like a location here
in Buffalo, New York,
where it's mother to son,
where Sophia Ananiadias
has raised her son Sam
in the business.
Now he's taken over,
and, boy, is she proud.
Welcome to Sophia's.
Open beef up.
How proud are you?
Very. He's my diamond
in the sky.
Here's the Sophia's omelet.
How much
do you love your mom?
Oh, a lot.
Everybody at the counter --
oh, mom, I know.
Those are still coming.
Chicken's done.
And my mind's still, you know,
you cook with love,
and the people are gonna
love you like family.
Mmm.
The food is awesome.
Almost ready now.
All homemade and fresh.
FIERI:
From serious breakfast...
Cinnamon apple
walnut pancakes.
There we go.
...to mom's Greek home cooking.
We're good to go there.
FIERI: This is where
you learned to cook?
Yeah, I've been here
all my life.
They've coming up next.
FIERI: Helping out mom
until six years ago
when he took over.
There's that.
I do everything here.
FIERI:
You heard him -- everything.
So you guys
make your own bread?
Yeah.
I didn't know what bread
was supposed to taste like
until I came to Sophia's.
What kind of bread is it?
It's just a traditional
white bread.
Give me the rundown,
brother.
We'll add some salt.
You're not measuring it?
No, it's all eye.
Baking's supposed to be
a precise act, brother.
Yeah, well, when you cook
with love,
you know, you always add
a little more sugar than salt.
All right, there we go.
There's that.
A little yeast.
Sure, so you're gonna eyeball
this whole thing?
Oh, yeah.
[ Whistles ]
You add the water, and then
we're gonna start adding flour.
Did we at least
measure this?
No, we usually
tell the consistency
when it stops sticking
to the bowl.
That's how your mom
taught you how to make it?
Pretty much, yeah.
That's real baking, man.
Yeah, we're gonna need
to add a little bit more.
Is it a little soupy?
Yeah.
Is this
starting to look right?
Yeah, it's starting
to look a lot better.
We're ready to get it out
of the bowl.
We set it right up on top,
tie it up, let the heat rise it.
So we'll let this proof.
Oh, this thing looks like...
Balloon ready to pop.
Gonna take this off.
We'll just pull enough
to start off with one pan.
Gonna flour it a little bit.
You're just rolling it
into itself.
Yeah, folding it over.
I mean,
very slightly kneading it.
You don't want
to overwork the dough.
No.
Because the yeast might
just get destroyed, you know?
Here we go. We gotta oil our pan
so the bread don't stick at all.
Pop it in there.
Two loaves in one pan?
Yeah.
Look at that.
That's beautiful.
Let it rise. So now we're up,
we're puffy. Looking good.
Yep.
Oven's set
at some temperature.
Yeah, hot enough.
[ Laughs ]
You just pop it in --
half-hour, 40 minutes.
And that's it.
Done?
Yeah. We're ready
to rock 'n' roll. Here we go.
That's the finished loaf.
So how long are we
gonna let it rest?
We can cut that right now.
You get the freshest --
the fresh bread. Get 'er going.
Cut it.
Still really hot,
you know?
Oh! Did you see that?
The steams
just awes everybody.
Oh!
You gotta be real careful.
That's awesome.
Yeah?
I mean,
it was just ba-jaw.
I want to be here
every day when that happens.
Slice me off
a piece of this.
All right. There we go.
Mmm! Can you smell that?
Look at that!
No drawn butter.
We want the real thing.
Mmm!
[ Mumbling ] Look how thick
the crust is!
Did you understand that
in bread-inese?
Yeah.
Oh! Bread's fantastic.
It's the best bread in town,
that's for sure.
It's the best!
FIERI: And a heck of a base
for their
signature sandwiches...
Open-face steak.
Oh! It's heaven.
And this buffalo favorite.
With the cut-fried bologna,
onions on there.
That's -- did that hit it?
Everybody has kind of like
a combination.
Fried bologna and onions --
you had me there. Good to go?
Homemade bread,
grilled onions
and about 400 pounds
of bologna.
Yes.
Stack it up real high--
and a little higher.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah. Put it right on top.
Mustard on here. And that's it.
You guys want to come down
and help me eat this.
Here we go. Mmm. It's great.
The bread's money. It's crunchy.
It's like you put breading
on the outside of the bread.
Mmm! You've taken some simple
comfort food like bologna --
the fat cooks to get some
of the caramelization...
The onions.
Yeah. I like it, man.
Flip the omelets.
Everything here
is made from scratch.
There's that.
It's all about
having a good meal. Good.
That's all set.
Just make it like
you're supposed to be.
And that's what
you've taught Sam.
So that's almost ready.
And no matter what,
I'm gonna make it right.
Pick up on
the first chicken, please.
FIERI:
Just the way mom taught him.
The reason I come back
is because there's love
in the food.
Two open beefs. I love it.
I can tell you do.
What do you want me to do?
Tell me.
Just cut some pitas.
Served with love
is all right by me.
Well, this place
is, like, full of it.
I'm gonna give her more
on the side.
Don't meet a lot of 27-year-old
dudes across this country
that are really good cooks,
great chefs.
You got something else
going, man.
Oh. Thank you, man.
I appreciate it.
You're a gem, man.
Nice to meet you. Awesome.
FIERI: Now from one
home-cookin' spot to another,
but with a twist.
On Triple "D,"
I love finding places
that are reinventing themselves,
like the second-oldest
restaurant here in Atlanta,
The Colonnade.
Now after 80 years,
they're still serving
the Southern classics,
but wait till you see
what else they're cooking up.
I'm having kangaroo,
and it's delicious.
Pretty adventurous.
Fantastic.
They mixed it up
a little bit.
It's magic.
Here's your fried chicken
on white.
FIERI: You still got
your Southern comfort food...
The Southern-fried chicken
is excellent.
Black-eyed peas.
The mac and cheese--
now that's Southern.
And yet they still keep up
with some new things.
FIERI: Like blackened halibut
with blue cheese butter
or salmon over grits.
Tray up, please!
The food
is never boring.
FIERI:
And the folks around here
are willing to take the risk.
It's too good to waste.
Just trying to keep up
with the times.
FIERI:
And somehow Jody Stallings
is mixing the new stuff...
Best fish I've had.
...and the classics...
All right, guys,
are you ready?
...keeping the place the local
favorite it always was...
Fantastic dish.
...when her dad, Paul Jones,
bought it back in '79.
The menu seems to be
pretty straightforward--
good Southern food.
Fried chicken's gonna be
the same for 30 years,
but we needed
something different.
So they brought in
a culinary school grad...
Fresh tarragon.
Chef Ryan Cobb.
The owners told me
on my first day --
they said, "Okay, here's your
apron. This is your kitchen.
Make it yours."
FIERI:
And get a load of what Ryan's
doing to classic pulled pork.
Redneck sushi.
Never seen it
in my life.
Quite interesting.
It is.
It's a great twist
on sushi.
You got to be in it
to win it on that one.
This is a boneless shoulder?
Yes.
I like to use a dry rub.
Paprika.
You got garlic powder,
onion powder,
salt and pepper,
oil blend,
just a touch
of apple cider vinegar.
Apple cider vinegar.
Gonna whisk this
together here.
Just gonna rub it here
on the plate.
Now do we have a smoker
that we're gonna work with?
Homemade smoker, yes.
What, out of a refrigerator?
Take everything out?
Let me see this
contraption you built.
It's got the woodchips
underneath,
perforated pan.
Nice!
It works.
It's fairly concentrated.
You smoke it
for about 45 minutes.
Wow. Look at that.
Wrap it in some plastic
so it kind of sweats itself.
Kind of like
a little steamer.
Put belly-to-belly option
on two.
Belly-to-belly option
Hut.
I like this.
Look at all that juice.
That looks great.
Look at that.
It just falls right off
of there. You're on it.
So you just do
a little pull like this?
Toss it in a little bit
of barbecue sauce.
Then we'll start
making the sushi?
Yeah.
I've got some
cooked sushi rice here,
barbecue pork,
fresh scallion.
We'll roll.
Tuck it in.
Got it.
FIERI: And then get this --
they'll batter it...
And then you're gonna
deep-six this thing?
...and fry it.
She's ready.
There you have it.
What do you think?
Great barbecue.
I mean, for a countertop
thing like that,
I was really leery.
The onion's a nice little kick.
The chipotle mayo's great.
A little heat on that.
Good, man. I like it.
It's scary, but good.
My very first sushi.
Are you ready?
It's wonderful.
I've been eating here 60 years.
I don't care what you order,
dear. It's gonna be good.
Tray up.
This is the place
you got to come to.
FIERI: For the old favorites...
It's the best.
...and the new ones.
It's delicious.
You never get a bad meal.
Kind of like
walking into home.
Good drinks
and good food.
What else
can you ask for?
Every Friday night, you know,
there's gonna be, like, bison.
Right, elk.
Raccoon,
opossum, squirrel?
No, not yet.
FIERI: Up next,
Mexican comfort
in Jackson, Wyoming.
Mm! Snap!
And in Chicago...
I dig this.
...a funky fresh spot
ampin' up a breakfast favorite.
Rock-star dish.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Jackson, Wyoming,
and I'm about two miles
from the center of town
over in kind of
the locals' area.
Now, when you think of Jackson,
what do you think of?
Well, of course, outdoor sports.
But when it comes to food,
what kind of food?
Well, one of the first that
would come up is wild game.
Then you'd have
some steakhouses.
But do you think
of Mexican food?
Well, you don't
until you try this joint.
This is Pica's.
MAN:
Marinated shrimp tacos.
You can tell
that what they're making,
they're making because
they love what they're doing.
Chicken mole plate.
You know, it's like
when you go down to Mexico
and someone fixes you a dish
in a place you'd never expect.
That's what you get here.
FIERI: That someone is chef
and owner Andy Parazette,
a So-Cal dude
who left behind the surf
to open up this mountain
taqueria in 2001.
Were you always
in the restaurant business?
After college,
I started cooking
and learned
different dishes
from different parts
of Mexico.
Posole verde.
Posole, for me, is
a comfort food, you know?
WOMAN:
It's extremely fresh.
The cabbage, the pork,
everything is just --
it's amazing.
So, we're gonna do
the pork posole verde.
And so, what we have here
is fresh tomatillos
and jalapeños.
Next we take water
and fill it.
They're gonna cook
for about 25 minutes.
We're gonna take a sauté pan
and take julienned onions
and garlic.
And let that just sit
and caramelize down.
Yep.
So, we're gonna strain this.
And then we'll puree them.
Yes.
And then we add
a little cumin.
Ground cumin.
Let 'er rip.
So, now we're gonna take
the blended-up tomatillo
and jalapeños and refry it
in the pot.
Then we're gonna add
the chicken stock
and our salt and pepper.
While that's cooking,
I'm gonna cut up our pork.
And we're gonna cook it
in this pan with what?
Yellow onion and garlic.
And cook that
for about 45 minutes.
All right.
Pork's ready to go.
PARAZETTE:
Everybody in the pool.
Big splash.
And our hominy.
And we let it cook for
another 20 to 30 minutes.
All right.
So, fresh cabbage.
Fresh onion.
Mexican cheese.
Fresh cilantro.
Twist of lime.
And the fried tortilla.
Got a little hot sauce?
Mm.
And not that this needs
hot sauce,
but there's just something about
all the times I've had posole
that I got to have
a little bit of that tang.
It's the freshness
of the cilantro
and the crunch of the onion
and the cabbage.
And the pork is ridiculous,
fall-apart tender.
Mmm!
Snap!
There's your posole verde.
It's kind of addicting.
The spicy
with the sweet and tangy.
When you live in a destination
resort like Jackson Hole,
one of the places you always
recommend is Pica's.
And I'm gonna tell you
something, man.
This would be outstanding
in California.
This is remarkable
all the way out here.
Great job.
Thanks a lot.
FIERI: Now we're going
from mountains to Midwest,
where the pork's
spicin' up breakfast.
I'm here in the Bridgeport
neighborhood of Chicago
about a mile away
from where the White Sox play
to check out a place
that I hear has great food
and a great story,
about a family of six
that lived above a bar
that they eventually turned
into their own restaurant
that's serving organic,
farm-to-table comfort food.
This is Nana.
Chicken sandwich,
farm greens.
It's just phenomenal.
We have the shrimp
and oyster po' boy.
Today, I'm having
the duck biscuits and gravy.
Oh, I love Nana's.
FIERI:
And there really is a Nana...
I named it
after my mom.
...Mexican-born Maria Solis...
Hi, ladies.
...whose 4 kids
opened this joint in 2009.
That would be Omar,
Ready?
Christian...
Breakfast burrito.
...Marco,
Side of bacon, please!
and Michelle.
Chilaquiles.
Basically, all we've done
is taken a lot of these
comfort dishes inspired
by mom's home cooking...
FIERI: And gave the recipes
to high-end Chef Guy Meikle.
Huevos ranchero.
He is on the par with all
the great chefs in town.
FIERI: And now he's putting
the Nana spin on comfort food,
like this top seller.
Nanadict.
The what?
The Nanadict.
Variation on eggs benedict
with chorizo.
We're gonna make
the chorizo ourselves.
Correct.
I dig this. Okay, so we
rehydrate the anchos.
Yep.
So you pull seeds
and stems now?
Mm-hmm.
There we go. Hit it
with the water,
and just let 'em steep there
for what?
About 20 minutes, just till
they get nice and soft.
Yep, they're steeped. You're
gonna purée 'em right now.
So now that's puréed.
Right.
Now we're making
the cure.
Fresh garlic,
fresh thyme, cinnamon...
That's a mess of cinnamon.
Ground cloves, cayenne,
dry oregano,
smoked sweet paprika.
So all in.
Our ancho purée.
To the stove.
So we cook off the spices
for ten minutes.
Got it.
Need to chill it down
in an ice bath.
'cause we can't mix the warm
product into the cold.
Ground pork.
Where's this coming from?
This is from Gunthorp Farms.
All right. All of that in.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, we'll let this cure up
for about a week?
Yep.
So you're constantly
making this.
Yeah.
What's next?
We're just gonna sauté it,
olive oil.
We add a splash
of white wine vinegar.
Cool.
That's it.
Okay, what are we making?
Making poblano cream sauce --
fresh poblanos roasted,
2 quarts
of heavy whipping cream.
The whole milk also?
Yep.
Doctor.
Scalpel.
How about tomatillos?
Tomatillos -- that'll work.
I didn't have any scalpel.
Tomatillos.
S and P.
A little bit now,
little bit at the end.
Okay, so we let this come up
to a boil?
Yep. So now
we're gonna add
our sour cream, cilantro,
and salt and pepper.
Hit it
with the immersion blender.
Mix it all up,
and that's it.
Okay, what are we making?
Pupusas.
I see the masa,
harina de maiz.
Yep.
FIERI: That's corn flour.
This is a cheese pupusa?
Yep, cheese pupusa, raw milk,
jack cheese, olive oil,
water.
Okay.
Little bit of kosher salt.
Okay, so you mix
the pupusa thoroughly.
A little extra salt.
Black pepper.
So now you form it out.
2-ounce ball.
Now you hit the mold?
Yep.
There we go.
Drop the pupusas and home fries
in the deep fryer.
Little bit of salt.
Okay.
Two deep-fried pupusas, home
fries, house-made chorizo.
Of course.
Two poached eggs.
Here eggy, eggy, eggy.
Poblano cream sauce,
wild arugula and spinach
with orange vinaigrette.
First, I got to just try
this chorizo by itself.
Mmm, tons of flavor. Mmm.
The crunch and the texture
of the pupusa --
mmm -- rock-star dish.
I knew this guy
was gonna be able to do it
with a name like Guy.
Come on.
The Nanadict --
it's fantastic.
It's the best chorizo
I think I've ever had.
Their food
just speaks for itself.
Organic and local
sustainable food
was something that we wanted
to be a part of.
Chicken sandwich, farm greens.
This place does it
really, really well.
It's home-style cooking
that is worth leaving home for.
I like coming here.
This is perfect for me.
What you have going on in here
is what everybody really wants.
Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it. Thank you.
Nana, thank you.
Nice job.
Thanks.
FIERI: Comin' up,
we're stickin' to Chi-Town
for more of mom's recipes.
Can I kiss you?
Congratulations.
Oh, boy, I knew this...
This time, Italian-style...
It's like a real-deal
Italian ham and cheese.
...and all in.
You're like a blackjack dealer
at the Flavortown casino.
♪♪
So I'll tell you something
that happens to me
all the time.
Friends will call me and say,
"Hey Guy, man, I'm stuck
at this airport on a layover
"you got any 'Triple D' joints
that are close by?"
Well I've got one for ya.
I'm about a 15-minute cab ride
from Chicago O'Hare
and I'm here
on North Harlem Avenue
to check out
some real-deal Italian.
This is Rex Italian Foods.
Muffaletta pie.
This is genuine Italian food.
Tortellini salad.
The best Italian food
I've ever had.
You feel like you're in Italy
when you come in here.
FIERI: From the scratch-made
food Pina Pinello grew up on
back in Sicily
to the look and feel of
an Italian home.
Everybody come in the store
is like my family.
If you're looking for something
that's homemade, made with love,
then you've definitely found
the right place.
FIERI: That's Anthony Pinello,
who started out
making deliveries
in high school.
I've got nine sausages
going up.
FIERI: Now he's cranking out
his mom's family recipes
The Arancini is up!
and rolling out
his own creations
like this bad boy.
Sicilian schiacciata.
It's like
this great ball of amazingness.
If a pizza met a sandwich
and had a baby,
boom, you've got
your schiacciata.
Schiacciatas?
Schiacciata,
it means flattened in Italian.
All right, let's go.
So here we're gonna make
our wet ingredients
for our dough.
Okay.
We put our salt
and our sugar
and then we put
our fresh yeast.
A bunch of it.
Mm-hmm.
We have our water,
we add half to this bowl...
Half to the other
to let that dissolve.
Exactly, whisk it.
It smells great.
Combine those.
Then we add
our Italian olive oil.
Whoa!
That's the secret ingredient.
So all this goes together
into the mixer with the flour?
Right.
Okay.
Okay, so now
let's make the dough.
Durham flour,
high gluten flour.
Potato granules,
also known as potato flour.
Really?
Yeah, don't ask me
why we use it,
it's just my Nona's recipe.
And you don't question Nona,
just go with it.
That's right.
And now we'll add
the wet ingredients.
We mixed it up,
it had a chance to rise.
Then we'll punch it down
a little bit.
Now we'll portion it out.
We use about three pounds
for one schiacciata.
It smells great,
that fresh yeast.
So we put
a little flour in here,
put a little semolina flour
into our pan, too.
It keeps it from sticking.
Yeah.
Just once through the top,
once through the bottom.
That's it.
Lay it out,
pull it to the corners.
That's it.
Are we gonna let this proof
before we top it?
Yeah, we let it rise
a little bit.
Okay, dough's out.
So we start building
our schiacciata.
Take the mozzarella...
What are you doing?
You don't do it on both sides?
No, what you do,
we're gonna close it up.
It's a giant calzone?
That's a good way to put it.
It's a pizza strudel, basically.
This is Italian
prosciutto cotto.
Cooked prosciutto.
Cooked prosciutto, right.
Every one knows the dried,
cured prosciutto,
that's the one
that's kind of like
its more famous cousin.
In the States we call that ham.
Right.
Okay, then after that
we put the pepperoni down.
You're like a blackjack dealer
at the Flavortown casino.
Yeah, right.
And then some fried peppers.
You fried 'em?
Hm-mmm, we use a deep fryer.
It gives it a little color,
gives it a little texture,
and then we add...
More cheese.
More cheese, yeah.
Then we just...
You just put it to bed.
...fold it over, yep.
Press the edges over here.
This is like,
stromboli gone wild.
Then we put a little egg wash,
we throw a little more
semolina flour on top
and that's it.
Then we go straight
to the oven with it.
What temp?
450, for about 20 minutes.
For 20 minutes?
Yeah.
Okay, so now it's out of
the oven, it's cooled down.
Right.
Now for service?
We take it out of the pan.
We're gonna cut it
in our eight strips.
Holy ham and cheese.
Then those strips individually
get tossed on the panini grill
to give it the grill marks
and warm everything
else up inside.
I can hear the snap, crackle...
Yeah, you can hear the sizzling.
It's ready to come off
the panini press.
You just cut that in half,
there you go.
Italian ham and cheese
with some peppers
and some pepperoni.
Yeah.
Mmm, you've got
that semolina flour
on the outside
which gives that nice,
little, crusty texture.
The pepperoni and the ham
and the peppers
infuse that flavor
into the dough.
Mmm, prosciutto cotto
is nice and tender
and not too salty.
You know, the fried peppers
coming in there.
I mean, mmm, excellent.
It's like a real-deal
Italian ham and cheese.
A ham and cheese,
Sicilian-style.
Sicilian schiacciata.
You can't describe it.
You have to come in here
and experience it for yourself.
Brittany Arancini!
I'm always torn
with what to get,
cold food, salads,
hot food,
even stuff to take home
and make yourself.
I actually grew up with a lot of
the products they sell,
and a lot of it
you can't find anywhere.
I never knew
where my nony got it.
It's awesome that I have
the stuff available to me.
The passion that the employees
have for the food
goes right into the food.
And to me
that makes it great,
no matter what you have.
Sicilian schiacciata.
Thanks for lettin' us come here.
Now on the camera,
can I kiss you?
Congratulations.
Oh boy, I knew this...
You guys gotta come down here
and see them.
So that's it for this road trip,
but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be lookin' for you
next time on
"Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
You can see that I was
waddling into it.
[ Laughter ]