Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Batter up!
...it's a first-class ticket...
Show us your magic.
...to the far east
of Flavortown.
Fantastic. That's good.
'Cause I need some more food.
We've got an American-Asian
combo in Seattle...
That is
really rocking chicken.
...Korean comfort in Chicago...
-Oh, yeah.
-Very nice.
...and in Hawaii...
I should wear
a life preserver right now.
...a boatload of real-deal Thai.
It's the long-lost USSS Duck
in Flavortown.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Chicago
in the Lincoln Park area
with the one and only
Chef Rocco DiSpirito.
We're here to check out a place
where a brother-and-sister team
have been rocking out
some creative Korean
for over eight years.
Chef, what are you doing?
Dude, I think it's closed!
No, it's right here.
This is Del Seoul.
♪♪
Pork bento coming up.
WOMAN: They're really isn't
anything like it
because of the different
cultures that they use
to incorporate in their recipes.
Kimchi fries.
MAN:
It's everything you could want
when you're looking
for ethnic food.
Two shrimp tacos.
MAN #2: It's not your mom
and pop's Korean restaurant.
It's taking it
to the next level.
FIERI:
Yep, it's not mom-and-pop,
but there's still some pretty
slick family magic going down,
brought to you by siblings
Peter and Irene Jeon.
How would you
describe the food?
More Californian
Korean food.
But you're doing it in...
Surprising ways.
...in surprisingly
different ways.
Yeah.
-Right.
-The food is really good.
I really enjoy the wings a lot.
K-town chicken wings.
WOMAN: The K-town chicken wings
are amazing.
The perfect blend of sweet,
tangy.
You have a little bit
of heat at the end.
All right, Chef,
so let's see this.
We're making
our chicken wing sauce.
So, we're making
a small batch, I can tell.
Yeah, we're making about
100 orders right here.
-Wow.
-Wing, wing, wing, wing,
wing, wing, wing.
Well, let's just get into it.
55 pounds of brown sugar.
Vinegar.
So, that's just
white distilled vinegar?
Mm-hmm.
Soy sauce, cooking wine,
oyster sauce.
Oh, yeah.
Very nice.
Sesame oil,
honey, white pepper.
Here we've got
our herbal tea,
a combination of Szechuan
peppercorns and cloves.
Ah.
We mix everything together.
Next, we got
our chili garlic paste.
And are you making
this chili garlic paste?
Yeah. We take a little bit of
vegetable oil, fry the garlic,
and then we add
crushed red chilies.
We'll just add
orange peels.
Now, how long is this
gonna sit here and steep?
About four hours.
You want the oranges to flavor
the rest of the sauce.
All right, Chef,
now we're getting into wings.
Show us your magic.
Just cut straight down,
pop that open.
Okay.
We'll cut right here,
and then we're just
gonna pop it.
Pull the bones
with your fingers.
That's actually
brilliant technique.
Cut this tip off.
Okay.
We got two bones.
Twist the small end.
Ah!
And your pop is done.
I don't -- I mean,
can you do that again?
[ Laughs ]
Huh?
Yep.
After the wings are lollipopped,
we're making a dry rub.
Salt, granulated garlic,
chicken base,
some white pepper,
ground ginger.
Okay.
And we're ready
to season them.
All right, so, this gets
mixed up, sits for four hours,
and then fried to order.
Double-fried.
So these have been fried,
cooled, fried?
Yeah, so they're nice
and crispy on the outside.
Now you're taking
the uncooked sauce.
We're just gonna
throw our wings in,
give it a quick toss,
and they are finished.
Wow, look at the way
that comes together.
Scallions,
toasted sesame seeds.
One warning --
This is really hot, so...
So, the hot part
would be the fact
that it came out of the fryer
just moments ago,
candied up with a sauce
that would burn your skin off.
Right, pretty much. Yeah.
Okay, good talk.
♪♪
Whoa!
Yeah, that's lights out.
The crisp
that you've put on this is...
Insane.
The lollipopping elevates
the whole appreciation
and the whole representation
of the wing.
You have the perfect balance --
sour, salt, sweet, bitter.
That is masterful.
The meat itself
has got good flavor.
Right.
My opinion,
the top was the orange.
Just getting that little essence
of the orange at the end.
Well done, man.
SERVER: K-town chicken wings.
I dream about them every night.
MAN: The sweet and sour Korean
barbecue sauce are great,
and there's really nothing bad
I can say about them.
Except for all that
will stick to your bread.
I should have brought
my son's bib in, I think.
There you have it.
Free bibs.
Come on down.
-Panfried dumplings ready.
FIERI:
Where did you learn to cook?
Uh...
Just --
Good answer.
Can we do that again?
Okay.
Chef, where'd you learn
to cook?
Uh...
[ Laughter ]
I learned from my mom,
and then I lived overseas
and worked in Thailand.
Nice.
And then Korea?
Yeah, and then Korean.
How'd you get to Chicago?
Well -- Yeah.
Took the train, bro.
After I left Korea,
I came back here,
and my sister and I
opened up this restaurant,
and, well,
the rest is history.
WOMAN: Amazing food.
You can get unique things
like poutine fries.
Kalbi poutine in the window!
The kalbi
is a beef short rib.
It gets placed onto the fries.
WOMAN #2: And then
with the cheese, sour cream,
and the pickled onions, it just
is overall a satisfying bite.
So, what are
we into now, Chef?
We're going to make our beef
marinade for our kalbi poutine.
So, what we got is
soy sauce, sugar.
Okay.
This is probably enough
for maybe 1,000 pounds
of meat right here.
Ground onion and apple.
It covers a lot of ground,
flavor-wise.
Yeah.
Garlic, rice wine, black pepper.
Weedwacker.
[ Imitates
Weedwacker whirring ]
Let's start braising.
We're gonna throw this, our
cooked short rib, into a pot.
Water, beef marinade,
yellow onion, carrots,
daikon radish,
sesame oil, chili flakes.
Now, how long are we gonna
let this simmer?
For about two hours.
This looks just fantastic.
We're just gonna hand-shred
the short rib.
Pour the jus
over the top of it?
Yep.
We're gonna take our fries out,
season them very simply here.
Just salt, garlic powder,
granulated garlic,
Korean chili powder.
Oh, cool.
And then some crushed
parsley's in there, too.
Okay.
You see how he subtly
put the fries away from us?
Yeah.
Here, we can put them
back over here.
Yeah, I saw it.
Don't do this. You're not
gonna have any dish left.
Put the fries right on.
Top this with some short rib,
white cheddar,
and spicy Jack cheese.
In the oven for how long?
Just to melt the cheese?
For about a minute.
Yeah, just to melt the cheese.
And here it comes.
Yep.
Sour cream, scallions.
Green scallions.
Picked red onions.
Getting
the perfect bite here.
Yes.
You need a mixture
of crisp fries and soggy fries.
And then you want the beef
and the cream, of course,
and you got to have
some of that onion on top.
Onion's key.
Yeah.
I've already had two bites,
and he's still talking.
Uh-huh.
You give it a ton
of the kalbi beef.
You're crushing them.
Right.
The pickled onions
really add the counterbalance.
You need that acidity
coming through.
And I love the little refreshing
creaminess and acidity
that you're getting
from the sour cream.
Talk about wanting
to give you
a traditional dish
like a poutine,
but put a Korean twist to it
and keep it balanced.
You did it.
Guys,
I have a kalbi poutine.
That poutine is definitely gonna
fill you up and warm you up.
WOMAN: The fries are crispy
and buttery.
The meat is juicy.
Bibimbop, ready to go.
You can try all sorts
of restaurant in the area,
but Del Seoul is definitely
one of the best.
Korean food with a twist
is exactly what you're doing.
You've been rocking it
for eight years.
Oh, you got a lot more coming.
All right. Thanks, man.
Nicely done, Chef,
nicely done.
All right, great, great.
Thanks.
Nice job, brother.
Good job, Rocco.
Huh?
Watch out for this guy.
♪♪
FIERI:
Up next, in Kona, Hawaii...
The wheels are off
the wagon, folks.
...a fantastic
family-run spot...
This is crazy.
...serving up some Thai
that'll make you fly.
I would fly from California
just to come have this
at least twice a year.
♪♪
MAN: Whoo-hoo!
You know, I don't think
it's very surprising
to "Triple D" fans --
I love Asian food.
I mean, Chinese, Japanese,
Korean, Vietnamese,
and one of my
all-time favorites, Thai.
I mean, I love it for breakfast,
I love it for dinner,
I love it for lunch.
I love when it's fresh,
I like it when it's old,
I like it when it's cold,
I'll eat it with a fox in a box,
in a tree with a bee,
and a goat -- Oh, I'm sorry.
Anyhow, well,
I'm in the big island of Hawaii,
and it's that much closer
to Thailand.
You know what I'm looking for?
Some Original Thai.
♪♪
Hot Thai shrimp!
If you love Thai food,
this is the spot.
The beef salad.
Everything they make here
is perfect.
All of it?
I mean,
is it really Thai-rrific?
[ Laughter ]
It reminds me
of being back in Thailand.
FIERI: The authenticity
comes from the O.G. herself,
Thailand's own Sa-ing Schueler.
How long have you been
on the island?
I came here 1985.
Oh, you were
just a little girl.
[ Laughs ]
I was 25 when I came.
No, you weren't!
Are you one of the owners?
The only owner.
Owners are mean
and old and gray.
You're nice and young
and smiling.
Oh, thank you.
This is Thai food,
but it's not just Thai food.
It's a whole mixture.
Right, right.
In between
Thai and Chinese.
You should
"Thai" some Chinese.
[try]
[ Laughs ]
I'll be here all week.
Try the duck.
SERVER: Triple S duck.
The crispiness and
the tenderness of the duck
combined with the flavors
of the sauce
really makes it
a perfect dish.
I've never tried anything
like this in my life.
What are we gonna make?
SSS duck.
Why so many S's?
Spicy, sweet, and sour.
It's the long-lost USSS Duck
in Flavortown.
Okay, Admiral,
dunk the duck.
We're gonna put it
in hot water.
Put the ginger.
A lot of cinnamon.
Garlic.
Star anise.
Red onion.
Black peppercorn.
Yeah.
Brown sugar, five-spice.
That much five-spice?
Yes.
We're loading for war here
on the SSS Duck.
Soy sauce, squeezed soy sauce,
Korean soy sauce.
Low-sodium?
Yes.
Vodka.
In the old traditional
Thai cooking,
add the vodka.
All right, how long's
that gonna simmer?
45 minutes.
It's all right here,
right now on the USSSS Duck.
The duck
is done and cooling.
Now what are we making?
We're gonna make
the SSS sauce.
Fish sauce,
vinegar, sugar, and --
Sriracha?
Yes.
So, that's cooked down
for 45 minutes.
Now we add that.
Fried garlic and onion.
We're gonna bone the duck.
Now we're just gonna dip it
in batter.
Yeah.
All-purpose flour, water.
Soy sauce.
Paprika.
Fry it.
Okay.
Bring the duck.
It's good-luck duck.
I'm gonna cut the duck.
SSS sauce.
I should wear
a life preserver right now.
Scallions.
Sri Lanka lime leaf.
And some carrots.
Is it cabbage or lettuce?
Cabbage.
We're taking on torpedoes,
the USSS Spicy Duck.
This is crazy.
You get that cinnamon,
that star anise,
a bunch of that five-spice,
but the duck is super-tender.
The cabbage is adding
a little texture,
so you're not just getting
the same note.
I would fly from California
just to come have this
at least twice a year.
Fantastic.
-The sweet, sour, spicy duck.
Sweet, savory, spicy,
super-crispy, moist meat.
Why don't you try to use
some descriptive words?
Okay.
I'll work on that.
MAN: It's original food, and
it's a family-run restaurant.
You've got the mom cooking
in the back,
daughters out here
running the restaurant.
FIERI: And a third-generation
is already in training.
Do you ever work here?
Sometimes I help.
Picking the basil.
Like, picking the basil.
That's a good job.
What do you call Grandma?
-Yay.
-"Yay" is "Grandma" in Thai?
Yeah.
MAN: There's plenty of Thai
restaurants around here,
and this is the only one
that we come to
because of the family
and the food.
-Thai pork larb wrap.
You know, it's not like
your traditional wrap.
It's a Thai version of it.
You've got the juicy pork,
you mix a little bit
of the peanut sauce with it,
you've got
an amazing bite right there.
What are making next?
Larb wrap.
Larb.
Larb? L-A-R-B?
Yes.
We wrap the larb.
So, you can make a lot of
things -- chicken, beef, pork.
Right.
Okay.
We're making it with what?
Pork.
Fantastic. That's good.
'Cause I need some more food
after the whole half
of duck that I ate.
We're gonna make
the peanut sauce.
Oil, curry paste,
coconut milk, paprika.
More coconut milk in there.
Okay.
Peanut butter.
Yes.
Sugar, water.
We're gonna put this in here.
That's just the sauce for it?
Yes.
All right, what are
we gonna do next?
Pork larb.
Oil, pork.
So, we brown it first?
Yes.
Lemon juice and fish sauce.
Onion, lemongrass.
Cilantro or green onion?
Cilantro
and green onion together.
The Sri Lanka lime leaf.
Rice powder.
To tighten it up.
Yes.
What do you got over there?
Curry fries.
Curry fries. The wheels
are off the wagon, folks.
I'm gonna bring my tortilla.
Mayonnaise.
Scoop from here.
There we go!
How do you eat larb
in Thailand?
You can dip this.
Dip it in there?
Yeah, or you can
just bite like that.
I've been to a lot
of Thai restaurants.
I have never had
a larb burrito
with curry fries, ketchup,
and a side salad.
[ Laughs ]
That's a first.
The flavors are delicious.
The pork's got
a good amount of fat.
Nice little kick
of the mayonnaise.
♪♪
The peanut sauce
is delicious.
I would love to have
more burritos like that.
[ Laughs ] Thank you.
SERVER:
Larb wrap with pork.
Really an unusual,
unique flavor.
Very tasty with
the peanut sauce. Delicious.
Mango curry chicken!
Nobody brings the sweet
and the spice like this place.
This is superb.
The food's delicious.
Thank you so much.
And you're wonderful.
Thank you.
Nice job.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, a crazy
chicken joint in Seattle...
[ Imitating
chicken clucking ]
...adding Asian flair
to their sandwiches...
Mmm. You could fry up an old
sock and put that on there.
... and loading up
the Bowl O' Shame.
My friend, you need to have
a license to wield this.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Seattle, Washington,
in an area known
as Capitol Hill,
or "Cap Hill" if you're a local,
to check out a joint
that's serving up the kind
of food everybody loves.
No, it's not spaghetti
and meatballs.
Nope, you're wrong.
It's not --
No, it's not barbecue.
No, it's not
Philly cheesesteaks.
And, no,
it's not Chinese food.
Listen, I'm gonna give you
a little hint.
It sounds like this...
Bok a bok.
Ah!
Just gave it away!
It's a fried-chicken joint.
This is Bok a Bok.
♪♪
Your Bowl O' Shame.
Fried chicken, Seattle --
This is it. It's amazing.
Rice bowl, 20 wings,
table 16.
Asian food
meets Americana food.
FIERI: Cooked up
by New York chef Brian O'Connor,
who trained in classic cuisine,
but ended up falling
for the bird.
I love fried chicken.
I've been in fried chicken
for over 20 years.
And we wanted to do
a fast-casual
being done really well by chefs
that have a lot of experience.
So, everything has
a little bit of an Asian flair?
Yeah, I want to say
it's Korean-esque.
Your soy sesame garlic.
I'm having the soy sesame
garlic chicken sandwich.
It's got fried chicken,
the lemon aioli,
and a sesame soy sauce.
It's delicious.
What are you gonna make?
The soy sesame garlic
sandwich.
The first thing we're gonna
make here is our brine.
Okay.
We're gonna start with
black pepper, kosher salt,
granulated sugar,
granulated garlic, bay leaf.
Crushed up.
I like it.
Crushed coriander,
toasted fennel seed,
and granulated onion.
Dig it.
A little warm water.
And then we like to cool it
down with some cold water.
Yeah, you don't want --
It's not chicken poach.
Nope.
Drop the chicken, eight hours.
Now we're gonna rack it.
Let it pull a little bit
of its moisture out.
Gonna help make it stick.
The batter will stick.
Okay, what's the batter?
Seriously, talk about it.
Tell me, what's the batter?
[ Breathes deeply ]
Was it childhood?
Eh, it's gonna be all right.
Yeah.
Batter up!
All right, we got
some cornstarch here.
That's a lot of cornstarch.
We've got some
gluten-free flour.
So this is also gluten-free?
Fantastic.
Kosher salt, a little
baking powder there.
Okay.
And then rice flour.
We add water, cold.
Warm if you want dumplings.
This is how I drink my vodka.
How do you have yours?
I normally go with mine
like that.
The vodka
helps the crust evaporate.
And then we're gonna
blend it up.
Aah!
[ Blender whirring ]
Use a whisk,
you'll be here all week.
Want to lick the spoon?
Now we've got
our brined chicken.
Nice tacky thighs.
I like to leave the fat on.
Fat equals flavor.
I want that.
Straight-up cornstarch.
Okay.
And then
we just drop it in,
just let it drain off,
and we'll drop it in the fryer.
Just like that?
Yep.
Comes out sort of like
a potato chip crust.
I like it.
What are we making now?
What's this?
The soy sesame garlic sauce
for our
soy sesame garlic sandwich.
Okay.
Where does all
the Asian influence come from?
I traveled
through Southeast Asia.
I love Asian food.
Oh, I'm a junkie.
Pretty simple sauce
I came up with --
crispy garlic, crispy
shallots, sesame seeds.
We're gonna blend these up,
make a tahini with them.
Boom.
I'll eat that gravel
all day long.
It does look like gravel.
We just add --
Sweet soy,
which is really thick.
♪♪
Okay, so, I'll have
6 gallons of that, please.
You like the sweet soy, but you
totally dig the little grit.
Mmm. You could fry up an old
sock and put that on there.
Or a flip-flop.
So, we're gonna put together a
soy sesame garlic sandwich here.
We have a lemon aioli
on the bottom,
crispy shallots on top,
baby kale
tossed in sesame vinaigrette.
It's a nest.
And the pièce de résistance --
chicken thigh.
And then we're gonna top it with
our soy sesame garlic sauce.
That's all she wrote.
Let me see
this funky batter.
I want to just
get a bite of that.
♪♪
Wow.
Brother, that's awesome.
The fry on that chicken --
It's potato chip
crunch all day long.
It's just enough thigh
to enough crunch.
Chicken's cooked perfectly.
Thank you.
Not overdone
with the aioli.
And not overdone
with the sweet soy.
So all of your finesse,
all of your creativity,
and all of your balance all
come through in the sandwich.
Dude, I mean, that is
really rocking chicken.
The sandwich is legit.
Your soy sesame garlic.
Enjoy.
It's really nice fried chicken,
and then you get
the lemon aioli --
nice and creamy underneath.
MAN:
Love the sesame soy on there.
It's actually
my favorite dipping sauce.
I get it by the jug.
They sell it separately.
Five drums, two biscuits,
table three.
Well, they're called Bok a Bok.
They better make good chicken.
Bok a Bok?
It's the sound a chicken makes.
Bok a bok.
You think they go "bok a bok"?
Because my chickens go...
[Imitates
chicken clucking]
Bok a bok.
Drumstick, five-piece.
So, now that you've got me here,
I need something else.
We'll do the Bowl O' Shame.
Bowl O' Shame
for you right here.
I think I'm gonna feel
a little bit guilty, yeah.
I got to finish this first,
then we'll go on
to the Bowl O' Shame,
and then I'm gonna walk home.
See you in a little bit.
♪♪
Bok a bok.
Welcome back.
We're at Bok a Bok
in Seattle, Washington.
So, a crazy guy
with a crazy chicken joint,
and I'm telling you something,
the chicken's crazy.
It'll knock your socks off.
When I think of Bok a Bok,
I think of, like,
comfort food with an edge.
FIERI: Sharpened by their menu
mash-up of Asian attitude
with all-American home cooking.
SERVER: Mac n' cheese.
With, like,
the kimchi mac n' cheese,
like, you have
the Korean influence,
but then you have something
that people are used to.
FIERI: And it's one of the key
components of this monster.
Bowl O' Shame, table 16.
The Bowl O' Shame is amazing.
It's got everything.
Tater tots, mac and cheese,
chicken.
The Bowl O' Shame.
And when you get as name
like that, you got to love it.
Tell me about
the monstrosity of whatever.
This is a bucket
of locally made kimchi.
Kimchi?
Give me some.
And I have it extra spicy,
'cause I like it to come
through in the mac and cheese.
Oh, we're gonna make food?
Yes.
We're not just gonna sit here
and eat this?
We're making
our kimchi cheese sauce.
We have our milk, water.
We use sodium citrate.
It prevents the fat
from leaching out of the cheese.
Kosher salt.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion.
There we go.
Korean chili powder, kimchi.
Shot of kimchi juice.
Right.
And then we use gochujang --
fermented chili paste.
Which is a staple
in Korean food.
When it comes to a boil,
we are going to emulsify
the cheese into it.
Fantastic.
Got it. Here we go.
This is sharp cheddar.
Boy, this is cheese sauce
gone wild.
Oh, look at that.
Creamy goodness.
♪♪
Every cheese sauce I've ever
had is missing kimchi.
Now we got to make
the four-chili hot sauce.
We got some Seattle stock,
otherwise known as water.
"Seattle stock."
Apple cider vinegar, white
distilled vinegar for heat.
Sweet sake,
otherwise known as mirin.
Habanero powder,
cayenne pepper.
One pepper.
Right.
Two pepper, three pepper.
Kosher salt, brown sugar,
fresh garlic,
Fresno chilies, red bells.
Okay.
A little bit of Korean chili
that's been bloomed in hot oil.
It's gonna add
a little smokiness to it.
Okay.
We're gonna simmer this
for about 30 minutes,
blend it, and strain it.
Chicken's gonna go down.
Spicy tots,
the Creole spice mix.
Oh!
Put it together.
We're gonna start by
taking the cheese sauce
and add in some kimchi,
Korean chili powder, noodles,
shredded cheddar cheese.
Extra cheesy, delicious.
Yep. Oh, yeah. That's...
Chicken thigh, crispy.
Right on top there.
Spicy tots.
And our four-chili
hot sauce we just made.
Uh-huh.
Some of that crispy garlic,
crispy shallots, green onions.
Korean chili powder on top.
The best part.
There's more part?
We like to top it off with some
of that lovely cheese sauce.
This is the shame
to set it off.
♪♪
Phenomenal.
It is so jam-packed with flavor.
♪♪
You got
the Creole tot heat,
kimchi, and then,
surprisingly enough,
the one that I love the most
is that four-pepper.
Voodoo with some tang.
Mmm.
It's this, baby.
♪♪
That is just fantastic,
'cause you got creamy,
and you've got heavy,
and you've got good salt,
and you've got good spice.
My friend, you need to have
a license to wield this.
That's a dangerous dish.
And your Bowl O' Shame.
MAN: I like it because it's all
mixed together with stuff
that you might not necessarily
think would go good together.
MAN #2: The Bowl O' Shame's
kind of hard for one person.
It's a lot.
Yeah.
One person?
It's hard for one family.
Yuzu, sesame sandwiches.
The food is amazing.
It's the best chicken
in Seattle.
It's really, like, next-level.
I'll tell you,
much success, my friend.
You market well, you present
well, you're super-creative.
Watch out for this guy.
You hear somebody go,
"Bok a Bok," run,
'cause it's really close by.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
My chickens don't have
a very distinctive "bok a bok."
You have Southern chickens?
They're Rhode Island Reds.
Okay, okay.
I don't have
any Rhode Island Reds.
Yeah, no,
they go, "Bawk, bawk!"
[ Laughs ]
♪♪