Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Let's see the magic.
...we're grabbing
and grubbing...
It's ridiculous.
...all kinds of comfort.
I can't find anything
I don't like.
Like fully loaded fries
in Gilbert, Arizona...
Sweet mercy, give me some.
FIERI: ...fantastic fried
chicken in Dallas...
Ooh, that's got
good crunch.
...plus, in Boulder, Colorado...
[ Whistles ]
...mega meaty pie...
You're O.G.
I like the way you roll.
...in a Godzilla-sized grinder.
My doctor warned me
that food that you see
is bigger than your head...
To eat it?
Run.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm on the northern side
of Boulder, Colorado,
to check out a pizza joint.
Oh, you want more?
Oh, no, it's just not
any pizza joint.
No, no.
This chef studied in Italy.
She's made pizza for the greats
on the east and west coast,
and from what I'm told,
you better watch out.
This is Audrey Jane's
Pizza Garage.
♪♪
Vita's Parm, table 5.
MAN: I've been to Naples
and had pizza there,
and this actually
in on par to that.
Hot Honey Disco up.
I think making pizza's
an art form,
and I think Audrey
has a knack.
It's like watching
a composer.
FIERI: Because Audrey Sherman
combined her passion for pizza
with the teachings of a maestro.
My mentor, Tony Gemignani,
I learned from him
in San Francisco.
Tony the famous Tony?
Exactly.
He's the heavyweight champ
of global pizza making
and throwing competitions.
After working at his joints
in San Fran and New York,
she came home to open up her own
with her brother Peter
and put her education to work.
It's the dough.
It all starts at the dough.
Let's see the magic.
SHERMAN: First up is
the high-gluten flour,
and then we have
some malt powder here.
We're gonna add
our cold water.
Got it.
Next, we're gonna
add our yeast.
Our biga.
Mother dough.
You call it biga?
I call it a biga here.
It's a lot "biga" [bigger]
than I thought.
I'm telling you, the way
that mother dough smells...
Oh, it's when you walk
into a bakery and you go,
"What is that?"
Now we've got our sea salt,
extra virgin olive oil.
Got it.
Bring it out, let it rest.
Then we'll portion it.
And then that's gonna go
in the walk-in for three days.
FIERI: Okay, sister,
where are we at?
We're gonna make our homemade
sausage for the Spicy Pig.
We got a Spicy Pig.
The Spicy Pig,
it's a pizza to die for.
The hand-pinched sausage
is so good.
-So, you grind the pork.
-We're gonna add our sea salt.
Grind up some fennel seed,
calabrese chilies,
and we've got some
local Colorado honey.
Is the sausage going on
to the pie raw?
Exactly.
It's cooked in the oven.
'Cause then you get
all that rendering fat
right onto that pizza.
Perfect.
You're O.G.
I like the way you roll.
Thank you.
All right, we're going
to make our sauce.
California tomatoes.
Paste.
A little sea salt.
Beautiful Sicilian oregano.
And build our crust.
Not her first rodeo.
Sauce on next.
We got our mozz.
[ Whistles ]
Natural casing pepperoni.
Like, a lot of pepp on these.
This thing's gonna be greasy.
That's why we call it
the piggy.
I love it.
Some fresh jalapeños.
And you're going to stick
more meat on this?
Our sausage
that we just made.
We also get some chopped garlic
and extra virgin olive oil.
Okay, that's good, good.
In we go to the oven at 650.
About six or seven minutes.
Good-looking pie.
Then we get oregano
on there.
Like we're blessing
some spirits or something.
Exactly.
All right, good to go.
The crust is outstanding.
Thank you.
When you're going to the extent
that you're going to here,
starting with the mother,
or the biga, it just shows.
The sausage is great.
The Sicilian oregano
is dynamite.
The right sized pepperoni,
the roasted jalapeños
just giving a little
bit of that heat.
Mmm!
I can't find anything
I don't like.
The crust on that,
it's a meal in itself.
It's why you start
with the dough, huh?
"Doughn't" [don't]
forget it.
I've got a 20-inch
Spicy Pig.
Just the right level
of spice.
You can taste that fat
on the meat, it's really good.
It coats your mouth.
Got a sausage slice
and a veggie slice at the bar.
I see that you've got a little
bit of the New York pizzeria
look going with the slices.
Yeah, this town kind
of needed a slice house.
I really like the atmosphere
around here.
You can see the cooks
in the back spin the pizza.
We need another grinder,
guys, on the fly.
I came for the pizza,
but the meatball is amazing.
Here's that meatball
grinder for you.
Meatball is east coast, baby.
That's why I come here.
What's the story, sister?
SHERMAN: We're gonna make some
rolls for our meatball grinder.
So, we're going to use the same
dough as we did for our pizza.
Lay a little flour
at the bottom,
and let them fruit
for about a half an hour,
and then they're going
to go in our steam oven
at about 575 for five
and a half minutes.
All right, what are
we making now?
We're gonna make
some meatballs.
This is my mom's recipe --
My Italian mom.
Some grated parmesan.
House-made breadcrumbs.
Some oregano.
Of course.
Sea salt.
Garlic.
We add it to the beef.
And we got our eggs.
Be a super trooper
and get your scooper.
Perfect.
Roast these in the oven.
About 26 minutes at 400.
26 minutes?
We add them to our sauce after
they come out of the oven.
Okay, look at this.
We got our fresh bread roll
brushed with some garlic oil.
That's better than
most bakeries make.
Brush a little more
garlic oil.
Of course.
Now we've got our meatballs
and our homemade tomato sauce,
top it with some parmesan
and the shredded mozz.
It's gonna go in our oven
for about two minutes.
It's ready to go.
My doctor warned me
the food that you see
is bigger than your head...
To eat it?
Run.
♪♪
Mmm.
I like aggressive meatballs.
We got to have some flavor.
Your mom does you right
on that recipe.
I like the raw garlic.
That's a meatball lover's
meatball.
More cheese than probably
humanly necessary.
And the roll is really
the pièce de résistance.
Awesome job.
Thank you.
Matt, I've got
a meatball grinder outside.
MAN: I mean, it's
your season-ender meal.
You're done for the day,
you might as well go relax
for the whole afternoon.
Got an eggplant grinder
and a Tony G.
If you want the best pie,
you got to Audrey's.
You're a wolf
in sheep's clothing.
I like that.
Go get them.
-Nice job.
-I appreciate it.
Watch out for her.
FIERI: Up next, a fried chicken
emporium in Dallas.
All night long.
Serving it up spicy...
That's quite a hot mess.
...alongside a southern
favorite.
That's wrong in so many ways
that it makes it right.
♪♪
So, I love shooting "Triple D."
I travel all over the world,
I meet great chefs,
I try incredible food,
but you know one of my
favorite parts are the names.
Where do they come up
with these crazy names?
I've been to The Shaved Duck,
the Tattooed Moose,
Tacopocalypse, Miso Phat.
So, here I am in north Dallas,
and I hear about a place
making real-deal fried chicken,
and you're going
to love the name --
this is Whistle Britches.
[ Southern accent ]
Got wings in the window.
I've never had chicken
that's this moist
and crispy at the same time.
Pitmaster, table 1.
Whatever goes out
from the kitchen is perfect.
'Cause chef Omar Flores
is dishing out
a whole lot of comfort
with a Southern spin.
We pride ourself on being
a funky fried-chicken place.
We do homemade biscuits,
homemade pies,
a lot of creative
sandwiches.
Like this fiery favorite.
Hot Dang for you.
The Hot Dang is perfect balance
between different flavors.
The hot sauce goes very well
with the ranch sauce.
Excellent.
So, we're doing the Hot Dang.
It's kind of our take on --
Hot chicken, got it.
We're going to start with
our brine, Kosher salt,
a little brown sugar,
whole garlic cloves,
yellow mustard seed,
bay leaf,
coriander seed,
black peppercorn.
Chile de árbol.
Apple cider vinegar,
and fresh dill.
Okay.
A little hot water
to dissolve all this.
So we don't poach the chicken,
we hit it with some ice.
In goes in
our chicken cutlets.
Those are big.
This is Texas, man,
it's got to be big.
And how long we gonna
brine them?
16 to 24 hours.
Okay,
so what do we make next?
Our Nashville sauce.
First off goes our canola oil,
got a little
granulated garlic, cumin,
a little red chili flake,
paprika.
[ Whistles ]
It's gonna get hot real fast.
Cayenne,
a little brown sugar,
Kosher salt, toss
in our glycerin flakes.
Oh! That's going to tighten
this whole thing up?
Exactly, yeah.
We're going to strain our oil,
lose all the chunky
stuff in there.
It's a culinary term,
chunky stuff.
Right.
And then we're going to kind
of slowly emulsify it
with our habanero hot sauce
we make here in-house.
Let me get in
on some of that.
Done-zo.
Oh, what did
Lionel Richie say?
All night long.
[ Chuckling ]
Next step.
We're making the dredge
for our chicken sandwich.
We'll start off
with corn starch.
Corn starch is made to fry.
Magic crunch.
A little AP flour,
baking powder,
cayenne, chili, paprika,
black pepper, a bit of sugar,
and Kosher salt.
Okay.
Dry, wet, dry.
Buttermilk?
Yep, buttermilk wash.
Into the flour.
Take them, drop them
into the fryer.
-350?
-350.
Let's see this.
Got our chicken, we got
our Nashville hot sauce,
chicken goes on
the toasted Texas toast.
I always like when the
chicken eclipses the bun.
Top it off with some
homemade dill ranch.
Some bread-and-butter
pickles.
Making the pickles yourself?
Yes.
Of course you are.
To finish it off,
just a little bit of dill.
That's quite a hot mess.
It's definitely a
fork-and-knife sandwich.
♪♪
That's ridiculous.
The breading is light
and fluffy.
Good tang, good crunch.
A little sweet,
a little heat.
The chicken is
incredibly tender.
The brine
is doing its job.
That's a divine brine
here at
old Whistle Britches.
[ Chuckles ]
MAN: A little Hot Dang.
So, this is one of the chicken
capitals of Flavortown?
Absolutely.
I just like saying
the name.
It makes me think of exactly
about what it is.
Corduroys and somebody
walking fast?
Yeah.
FIERI: Hey, I'm not crazy.
That's actually where the term
"whistle britches" comes from.
Got to have a little
Southern accent, like,
"There's whistle britches
over there."
[ Southern accent ]
Whistle britches.
[ Normal voice ] See,
it sounds a little tougher
when you throw
the Southern accent on it.
Right, exactly.
Which goes right along
with this Southern staple.
The chicken and the waffles
is perfectly balanced.
I always choose this
when I come here.
Bone-in-chicken
on Chicken N' Waffle?
Absolutely.
We're going to brine this.
The house brine.
Let that go for 24 hours.
Next up?
Our black pepper
sausage gravy.
Good man.
We're going to start off
with a good,
healthy portion of butter,
ground breakfast sausage,
a little yellow onion.
So, once that's all
rendered out, we're going to add
some flour to kind of
make the brew.
Chicken stock.
-In house?
-Yes, sir.
Duh. Milk.
Heavy cream, very nice.
Yellow mustard powder,
a little pepper.
Worche-che-che-che-che-shire.
Worcestershire.
Hot sauce for a little kick.
-And salt.
-Salt.
And that's the gravy.
And next step?
We'll dredge our chicken.
We do it just wet dry.
It's a little clumpy,
but not too clumpy.
Just to get kind of
those nice little yummy,
crunchy bits on the chicken.
Can you see "Yummy bits here
at Whistle Britches"?
[ Laughs ] No.
Okay, so we're going
to fry our chicken off.
Pressure fry it.
Exactly.
In this Broaster,
which is the key,
makes it crisp,
makes it consistent.
-Makes it delicious.
We're ready to rock.
Waffle time.
♪♪
Ooh,
that's got good crunch.
Next goes our chicken.
This whole Texas bigger thing
has gone to his head.
Piece of watermelon.
Kind of lighten the dish
up a little bit.
Got some hot honey here,
and then we hit that
with sausage gravy
right on top of the chicken.
A little chives on top.
That's it.
This is ridiculous.
Mm.
That's wrong in so many ways,
but it makes it right.
Perfect.
Texture on the chicken
is gangster.
The sweet honey combined
with that savory gravy
is over the top.
Let me just dig down here to
the bottom to the flavor sponge,
the waffle.
[ Chuckles ]
Flavor sponge.
It's delicious.
-Chicken N' Waffles.
-It's a great mix of taste.
MAN: Can't go wrong
with sausage gravy.
You're in Texas, you smother
that on everything.
Two buddies of mine,
Chris is with
Operation Barbecue Relief,
and David Knight
from Old Hickory Barbecue.
So, in the world of fried
chicken, this is...
Phenomenal.
Whistle Britches in the window.
Omar for me is like
a food architect
the way he set
up his dishes.
He's up there with the best.
Dangerous chicken.
Yeah.
Dangerous.
-Appreciate it, man.
-Really dynamite.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
an Arizona spot
with a knack for the stack.
I mean, this is heaven.
From a barbecue
French fry mashup...
I want to see somebody be able
to eat that and not have a beer.
...to their spin
on a Mexican mouthful.
It actually makes some
other chilaquiles look
like their asleep.
Welcome back to
Whistle Britches!
Howdy.
It wasn't hat-wearing day?
That was yesterday.
Oh! Dang!
♪♪
So, this is what happens
to me all the time.
Someone rolls through a town,
they'll call me,
they say, "Guy, come on,
where do I eat?
Give me a great place."
Well, as the host of "Triple D,"
as a chef,
as their buddy,
I got to deliver.
There's so much pressure,
I don't want to send
them to a bad place.
But today,
the pressure's off of me.
We're in Gilbert, Arizona.
Chef Beau MacMillan,
what do you got?
Yeah, buddy,
I got my boy Seth,
worked with me
for eight years,
hooked up with this awesome
family, great concept.
This place really
stacks up!
-Did you really just say that?
-I said it.
-This is Grubstak.
-Yeah!
I can't believe
you said "stacked."
I had to.
♪♪
Chillax all veg out.
Grubstak's brought a really
unique concept that is a spin
on American classics.
We have the French toast
for you.
Foods that you like, and they
stack them on top of each other
into basically one item.
FIERI: And the blame
for this savory stacking
falls on the dude with food
on his brain and in his name,
Colton Grubb.
I literally was obsessed
with the idea
of putting things on fries.
What was the first
dish on the menu?
Sweet Lou's BBQ
after my grandpa.
He was a potato farmer,
and then made a name
for himself in the car business.
FIERI: And it's Chef Seth Widdes
who came on board
to bring grandpa's namesake
to the table.
Sweet Lou's BBQ out.
MAN: Half sweet potatoes,
half regular fries,
then throw a sweet barbecued
beef on top,
then on top of that is coleslaw.
-This is the barbecue stack?
-This is the barbecue stack.
Named after the famous
potato farmer.
Yep.
Here we got our beef.
Okay.
So, we're going to hit it
with our blended oil.
-Skirt, flank?
-We use the lifter.
-Lifter?
-Yes, off the rib.
Lot of texture there,
but you got to cook it down.
Exactly. We're going to
hit it with salt.
We're going to give it
a hard sear.
For 12 minutes.
And then what's the
braise going to be?
Pureed mirepoix.
The one thing we add
to our mirepoix is garlic.
Which I think should
have it anyways.
Celery going in, onion,
carrot with our water.
I'd like to comment on how nice
your mirepoix cuts are actually.
Very balanced.
It looks like sands
in the hourglass.
Beau, you got to
drink this now.
Sweet mercy!
Give me some!
[ Laughter ]
Here's our beef.
Now we're going to hit it
with a mirepoix puree.
Our house vegetable stock.
Going to give it a braise.
And then low and slow
for five hours at 325.
-Then shred it?
-Shred it.
Heating it on the stove
in the broth?
Exactly. All right,
next up,
we're going to make
our coleslaw.
We start with our mayonnaise,
Dijon mustard,
then we go apple cider
vinegar, and then honey.
We're going to take
that for a whisk,
and then lastly, we hit it
with some celery seed.
Then we're going to go ahead
and mix our cabbage
and our carrots together.
Sorry.
He clipped my hand.
And then we're going to add
our coleslaw dressing
into the cabbage mix.
I love coleslaw.
That's great.
Mmm! Delicious.
ACV and the celery salt.
It's time to build it.
So we have our hot beef
going down,
we take an applewood
smoked thick cut bacon.
Got it.
Barbecue sauce going
right over the top.
So it's everything you want
in a barbecued beef sandwich.
So, we take our fries, half
sweet potato and half regular.
We get that beef right dead
center there, barbecue sauce,
coleslaw right on top,
and that is the Sweet Lou's BBQ.
Beau, here is your fork.
Sorry, I meant
to give it to you.
Mmm!
Holy mercy.
There's no question of flavor,
fries are great,
slaw is the perfect
counterbalance.
I mean, this is heaven.
Yeah.
Great meat, a lot of it.
-Wow!
-Absolutely.
I want to see somebody be able
to eat that and not have a beer.
Big time.
Beer helps it go down.
-We have the Sweet Lou's BBQ.
-I love the meat,
it's nice and tender.
AURILIA: I love the acid in the
sauce and this creamy coleslaw.
It blends nicely
with the whole dish.
I think we've seen this cat
before, Rich Aurilia.
Mainly we know him
as a San Francisco Giant.
Is this what I'm finding
when I start coming to Gilbert
and Phoenix?
The last few years, the food
scene, it's really taken off.
We have a great population.
They believe in high quality.
You're the mayor of Gilbert?
Yes.
And you eat at Grubstak?
I love Grubstak.
We have your Chillax.
What else do you have up
your sleeve?
Our chilaquile.
We have the Chilaquiles for you.
The meat on that is fantastic,
the tortilla is great,
the cheese on it is fabulous.
So far,
ladies and gentlemen,
Beau MacMillan
still has a job.
-Yes!
-See you in a minute.
Yes! Yes!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back, we're at Grubstak
hanging out with the one,
the only,
Chef Beau MacMillan.
Chef Seth is his protégé
of stacking foods,
everything from tortillas,
to waffle fries, to you name it.
Grubstak, bacon biscuit.
I mean, it's just a matter
of layering
the different types of food.
You're getting the most flavor.
It's very good.
Hello.
We have your chilaquiles.
I've had the chilaquiles
numerous times.
There's something
special about it.
Okay, what are we making?
Our chilaquile.
Okay.
We're going to start off
with our chicken, some salt.
Got our thyme, dried sage,
and then we're going to hit it
with some blended oil.
He's doing good.
So, this is now going
to go in the oven.
For a hard roast,
start that searing process.
Okay.
We hit it with
our pureed mirepoix,
and then we also make
our own vegetable stock here.
Not bad.
Into the oven, what temp?
325 for two hours.
Two hours?
-Shred it?
-Yep.
And we're on our way
to chilaquiles land.
I'm dying to go.
[ Laughter ]
We're making the chili.
You put chili
in chilaquiles?
Yes.
[ Laughs ]
We do kind of
a Southwestern spin.
So, we start off with some
blended oil in our pan,
our mirepoix,
roasted red bell pepper,
and we got our hot sauce,
tomato paste going in, as well.
Jalapeño in next.
Going to go garlic in,
and then lastly,
we add our first half
of our diced tomatoes.
We're going to just go
ahead and puree it up.
Easy on the blue shirt
over here.
Beau, shield me.
Next up, we're going to go
brown sugar, coriander,
cumin, dark aged chili powder,
cayenne pepper.
The magical fruit.
Black beans, and then the other
half of those diced tomatoes.
That's going to cook down
for 30 minutes.
We hit it with our
fresh lemon juice.
Not only is this chili,
but it's vegan chili?
-Correct.
-What's our next step?
We're going to make
our ranchero sauce.
A little blended oil,
mirepoix again,
green bell pepper.
So we're almost going
holy trinity now?
Yeah. Jalapeño again,
raw garlic,
roasted red bell pepper,
diced tomatoes,
all those aromatics.
He likes the word
"aromatics" a lot.
-I noticed that.
-He does really like it,
and mirepoix.
So, we have our cayenne pepper,
aged dark chili powder,
and then lastly, our cumin.
Okay.
Our house hot sauce again,
and then to end with,
our acid, fresh lemon juice.
We're going to let
this go 20 minutes,
puree it to a fine liquid,
then ready to serve.
I'll see you, buddy.
We're going to make
our chilaquile next.
So, chicken down, our house
chili that we made earlier.
Yum.
Barbacoa sauce.
Oh, yeah.
Chilaquile filling
on the bottom.
Sweet goodness.
Crispy tortilla, filling,
cheddar in between.
Seth, make it nice,
don't rush it.
Got our filling again,
cheddar,
another crispy tortilla,
pour the rest
of that filling.
More cheddar on top,
right into a 500-degree oven.
-How long?
-35 seconds.
Goodness gravy!
We're going to hit it
with that house ranchero sauce
right over the top, and then
garnish with a green onion.
And this does traditionally
come with eggs.
In honor of you, we decided
to go eggless today.
You trying to get points
for that?
I love the chicken,
I liked where that
whole thing was going.
I really didn't think that
we had the true spirit
of chilaquiles
when we started this.
Beans, and vegan chili, and
you're going all over the place
to some ingredients
you wouldn't typically see.
But the ranchero sauce,
you get depth,
you get mouth-feel,
you get textures,
you can take a breath.
I haven't eaten in 46 minutes.
I was starving.
He hasn't eaten in
four to six minutes.
-This is awesome.
-It's really good.
It actually make
some other chilaquiles
look like they're asleep.
-Nice job, Seth.
-Thank you.
The only thing I didn't like
is sharing it with Beau.
[ Laughter ]
We have the chilaquiles
for you.
I really enjoy
the ranchero sauce.
It's very, very good.
The mix of the tortilla
is great.
French toast, Rancher up.
You can tell they really
enjoy what they're doing.
It shows.
Beau told me great things.
He said
this is unconventional,
there's combining,
and there's creativity.
So, I will award both of you
points in this.
Beau, congratulations,
you get to ride home in the car.
[ Laughter ]
And Chef, good luck,
'cause you're going to be
a busy man.
-Thank you very much.
-Way to go, Seth.
♪♪
So was that another righteous
road trip or what?
But don't you worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
-Mmm!
-I have never heard one person
eat food and moan.
Why can't I express myself?
Well why can't you
do it inside?
Because you do it
on a loud speaker.
Mmm! Mmm!
[ Laughter ]
♪♪