Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
...we're grabbing
global grub...
Hold on
a second here.
...all over the U.S.
Hello, food coma.
I'll see you in just a minute.
We've got Italian gone crazy
in California...
Dynamite dish.
...a taste of Colombia
in Miami...
This is
my kind of meal.
...plus in Hawaii...
I'm not messing around.
...fantastic
island flavor...
It gives me
goose bumps.
...real deal
and done right.
I can't get this
in my face hole fast enough.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, here I am
on the big island of Hawaii
and what am I looking for?
Some poke.
So, I do exactly what you do.
I call somebody that knows --
My buddy, Reno Henriques.
You know, from Fresh Catch,
the poke master of Oahu?
He says, "Don't worry.
I got you hooked up brother.
You got to go see
this guy named Nakoa.
Oh, you'll love him.
Raises a lot of money for kids,
the dude's born and
raised on the big island,
and he is truly a poke master."
And the name of the joint
is Umekes.
♪♪
Kalua pork up!
It's delicious.
It's always made
with lots of Aloha.
Abua poke bowl.
Some of the best fish
in the country.
FIERI: 'Cause it's straight
off the boat fresh,
something Nakoa Pabre grew up
with and came back to.
So, you were
a plumber first?
A plumber, yeah, but always been
the background cook
and helping all
the uncles growing up
and cooking food
and making poke.
Now you took it
to a restaurant.
I wanted to bring back
that old-school local flavor
that people
can come and enjoy.
Have a Kanaka poke bowl.
The Kanaka is traditional
Hawaiian poke.
He buys ahi from a lot
of local fishermen.
We're going to work
on our Kanaka poke first.
"Kanaka" means "local."
Okay, what makes
great poke?
Great poke has to be fish
that's fresh out of the water.
So, today we're going to
cut up a whole tuna.
Like the Hawaiian Dundee.
[ Laughs ]
We got about
a 50 pound tuna.
Oh, that's -- You can just
put that in my car.
There's a '66
Corvette convertible.
If you just wrap that
in some ice.
Put that out there.
There you go.
There's all these little bones
inside of this.
And for our poke, we only use
the best part of the tuna.
That's mean and clean.
Yep.
You don't know
how important it is
to have
a great fishmonger.
My fish market in Santa Rosa,
a big shout out.
They kill it.
So, now we're gonna
take this.
We're going to cube it.
You're like a surgeon.
Ohh!
Look at that.
This is a lot of work, bro.
So, next, we're making
our Hawaiian chili pepper water
Chili water.
So, we got the water,
Hawaiian sea salt,
our blend of Hawaiian
chili peppers,
garlic, and vinegar.
We're going to just
let that boil down.
Put it in the fridge,
let that cool,
and then we're going
to add our limu kohu.
Oh, I love when you
put the limu kohu.
"Limu" means "seaweed"
in Hawaiian,
almost like
a sea asparagus.
I got somebody right now trying
to write "limu kohu."
So, the beautiful poke.
First we add
our Hawaiian salt.
Sweet onions.
Green onions.
This is a different type
of seaweed.
It's called "ogo," and
we're gonna add our Aloha shoyu.
Hawaiian soy sauce.
Oyster sauce.
And then a bunch
of chili water.
For that flavor.
Nice!
I can already tell Reno
I'm trying this, right?
Call Reno right now.
Hey, brother.
I'm hanging out
with your buddy here.
What's up, bro?
Look at
that delicious poke.
You're the one that introduced
us to real Hawaiian poke
back in the day.
He's the understudy.
This guy is the real deal.
Be good, bro.
You're about to do
the poke taste test.
The rice with the
furikake, mac salad.
And boom -- That's our
poke bowl right there.
That's how you roll.
I'm not messing around.
Yo! It's delicious.
The fish is melting
in your mouth,
and you get all these
little textural pieces
from the ogo
and from the green onion
and from the cabbage.
And then you get the
sweetness of the rice.
Then you get a big bite
of the yellow onion
that really refreshes
your palate.
Oh, my gosh! I can't get this
in my face hole fast enough.
We just need
some rice,
and then maybe a cooler
and some beer.
WOMAN #1:
The Kankaka poke bowl.
Melts like butter
in your mouth.
It has just the right
amount of spice.
This is where you come
when you want poke.
FIERI: Or any authentic Hawaiian
dishes, for that matter.
WOMAN #2: It's one of the few
restaurants that can grab
different things
from different islands like
the Molokai Axis deer.
PABRE:
Molokai venison up!
He's just taken Hawaiian
traditional dishes
and made it his style.
I've got a heartbreaker up.
The heartbreaker,
it's a lau lau,
which is pork steamed
in taro luau leaf,
and they cover it with gravy.
Elevating it to a level
that's just divine.
Don't tell me we're
gonna cook food.
You're spoiled with
the raw already, huh?
Oh, my gosh!
We're gonna prep our lau laus
for our heartbreaker.
Pork lau lau, okay.
Yeah, we just got
a boneless pork butt here,
cut it into cubes.
And it's wrapped
in the taro leaves.
It's the Hawaiian spinach,
basically.
Grab foil here, take about
three or four taro leaves.
We'll add
three pieces of pork,
two of these pork fat
to retain that juiciness.
Take some of our salt,
sprinkle it all over,
and wrap our taro
leaves like that.
Seriously?
Throw 'em in the steamer
for about five, six hours.
You want that port
really tender.
Okay.
So, now we're gonna do
our fried rice.
Get some oil down,
we'll add our smoked pork.
We actually make it.
Really?
Portuguese sausage,
onions, carrots, cabbage.
We use brown rice.
I like it.
Add some shoyu,
garlic salt and pepper,
soy sauce, bit of oyster sauce,
sesame oil, as well.
Then we top it off
with some green onions.
There's our fried rice.
Beautiful.
Nicely done.
So, we got to pull
the lau lau out.
We're gonna make
our tempura batter.
We have our flour,
add some corn starch to that,
some salt, cold water.
We're gonna do
some whisking.
Take our lau lau,
toss it in flour.
You deep fry it
with the leaves, too?
You eat
the leaves, yeah.
I didn't see
that coming.
Get in our tempura batter,
put it in our panko.
We're gonna take this
right in the fryer.
And what's the
brown gravy made of?
Butter, flour, salt,
and then a little bit
of our Kobe drippings.
So, now we're ready
to plate our heartbreaker.
So, we put two big scoops
of fried rice down.
Okay.
Panko crusted lau lau,
our brown gravy, top it off
with some green onions.
And normally you put a
poached egg that you tempura.
Correct.
That would be
my heartbreaker.
[ Chuckles ]
Hold on a second here.
Stop the presses
on this one.
Bro, it's like pulled pork
meets collard green,
fried nugget of deliciousness.
Ridiculous.
Nice.
I'm not kidding you!
I've never had taro leaf
on the islands
ever taste that good.
Pork's perfectly seasoned,
the gravy's not really heavy.
Fried rice is great.
This isn't breaking
any hearts, dude.
This is like
next level lau lau.
WOMAN #1:
I have a heartbreaker.
It's excellent.
The pork is really good.
Very tender, very juicy.
It's got that crunch to it,
but that meat inside
is still so good.
FIERI: Come on!
Dude is that not crazy?
It's a tasty meal.
Good local food.
I've got
a Cajun fish tacos up.
We'll tell all our
friends to come here.
WOMAN #2: It's always a treat
to have Umekes,
you can't get
much better than this.
It gives me
goose bumps,
because to think
that you were a plumber --
Not that plumbers
are bad.
But this was your calling.
You crushed it.
Thank you.
Mahalo, brother.
Mahalo, bro.
FIERI: Up next, a true pasta pro
in San Carlos, California...
I expect nothing less.
...cranking out
not your everyday Italian...
Joyce in Topeka, do you want
to see it one more time?
...that involves one
surprising finish.
I didn't see that coming.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in San Carlos, California,
about 20 minutes south
of San Francisco.
I'm looking for this
family-owned Italian joint,
and I hear they make
incredible hand-made pastas
and pizzas, and the place
is just crazy.
Actually, that's the name
in Italian, and this is it.
Welcome to Pazzo.
♪♪
Pork ragu with cavatelli.
Pick it up.
I didn't know "Pazzo"
meant "crazy,"
but it's crazy because
of how delicious it is.
One house-made
fennel sausage pizza.
This is absolutely
authentic Italian.
One linguini with prawns.
It's a gem.
Andy does not do bad food.
FIERI:
But it's no sleight of hand
for East coast native
Andy Gambardella.
Most of the foods are
like the type foods
I grew up in.
Neapolitan-style, New York-,
New Haven-style Italian food.
How does this compare
to the other Italian joints.
Oh, it blows it
out of the water.
It's so fresh,
you can taste it.
We have
our smoked bucatini.
The smoked bucatini
is delicious.
It is a house-made noodle.
I'm not even sure
how he does it,
but he adds that smoky flavor.
Bucatini, without question --
I don't know about you,
but for me...
I love it.
...one of my all-time
favorite pastas.
Bucatini's got
a small hole.
Yeah.
Okay, I see that you've
got an extruder.
Let's take it for a run.
Let's do it.
We've got #1 semolina,
egg yolks only.
Okay.
Makes a nice,
rich pasta.
Some water.
Start mixing.
How long will this run?
For about 15 minutes.
Oh, that's beautiful!
You remember when
you were a little kid,
and you had Play-Doh,
and it came out
and you got excited?
That's what I'm going
through right now.
Dip it in the rice
flour, coat it.
Nest it.
Look at this little routine
you got going, though.
Oh, yeah. And then
it's going to go
into our smoker
for like 20 minutes.
We're actually
smoking the pasta?
We smoke the pasta.
I didn't see
that coming.
We don't want to,
like, crisp it up,
but you can taste
the smoke.
You're crazy.
Yeah, I am.
"Yeah I am."
I resemble that remark.
Okay, this is a simple
cacio e pepe sauce.
Cacio e pepe --
cheese and pepper.
It is one of the staples
in Italian food.
We're gonna drop
the bucatini first.
'Cause we're
reconstituting it.
Yeah. Drop that in.
Okay.
And we'll start
with a little pasta water.
Which has got a little bit
of starch in that,
so that'll
tighten it up.
Next is butter
and fresh-ground black pepper.
This is super key
in Cacio e Pepe.
You got to have
really good, fresh pepper.
And Pecorino cheese.
That nice, tangy,
salty Pecorino.
Absolutely.
Add more pasta water.
That's really
how you dial it in.
Pasta al dente.
Hello, food coma.
I'll see you in just a minute.
Nesting it right up.
And then we garnish it
with some more Pecorino.
♪♪
It's outstanding.
Thank you.
That's such a big,
full-bodied bucatini.
The smoke to this
is the perfect foil.
Mmm!
It's cooked the right way.
You use really good pepper.
And then you get the right
amount of cheese in there
with water to make the nice
sauce that coats the noodle.
All right, let me
show you something.
I teach this to my kids.
Don't make your bite too big.
You grab
a couple strands,
you pull it to the side
of your plate,
and then you lightly
twist it up.
One little bite,
Now enjoy it.
So, again.
♪♪
Oh, Joyce in Topeka, you want
to see it one more time?
Hang on. I love when people
call into the show.
♪♪
One smoked bucatini
with cacio e pepe.
That little bit
of smokiness to it,
it's just wonderful.
And the cheese on the top is
the perfect finish.
It's totally a show just
watching his dance back here.
What else should
I try on the menu?
The pizza.
It's definitely so good.
They have a great wood-burning
pizza oven in the back.
We love the crust.
It's thin. It's crisp.
It's that
New Haven char.
I got to be honest --
That's gorgeous.
With the sausage
that you grind in-house.
Mm-hmm.
Sautéed mushrooms.
Mmm. Fantastic.
Thank you.
The pizza is to die for,
and it's one of those places
you don't stick
to one dish.
All right Merlin, what else
you got up your sleeve?
A couple things. We could make
some ricotta gnocchi.
It's the lightest,
puffiest, creamiest gnocchi
you'll ever have.
FIERI:
All right, that's a no-brainer.
I'll have some of that
when we come back.
We're hanging out at Pazzo.
We'll see you in a bit.
♪♪
So, welcome back.
We're hanging out at Pazzo
in San Carlos,
just south of San Francisco.
This is
authentic Italian food.
Roasted branzino sea bass.
Pick it up.
The food is so fresh.
MAN: It's an experience
just having the pasta here,
and it's all homemade.
I used to own
a pasta factory.
FIERI: Which means Andy
Gambardella knows a few things
about homemade pasta.
One ricotta gnocchi!
Pick it up!
The gnocchi are as
light as a feather.
WOMAN:
It has wonderful artichoke
with a little hint of mint.
It's fantastic.
What makes great gnocchi,
in your opinion?
These aren't made with potato,
these are made with ricotta.
So, nice little,
light pillows.
Very light.
They melt in your mouth.
We've got some 00 flour,
whole-milk ricotta.
This is not when
you go for skim.
No.
Kosher salt
and some egg yolks.
Lightly work this
together,
just to where
it'll come together.
Throw it on the bench,
a little bench flour, roll it.
That's it.
I like it.
This is gorgeous.
You don't need
to do too much.
If he just looked
at this with a scowl,
he could get them
to fall apart.
Let's cook the gnocchi.
Okay chef, what kind of sauce
are we gonna make?
Fresh artichokes,
lemon, and mint.
Let's make it happen.
Olive oil, a little bit
of butter, fresh garlic.
You see how he pulls
it off the flame?
It's one of the great things
about cooking with gas,
not that you have gas --
Well, but you --
Okay, you know
what I meant, though.
I don't like electric stoves.
That's what I'm trying to say.
Now the artichoke.
This is salt
and pepper mixed.
And we're gonna put
the fresh mint, pasta water.
Let that reduce
a little bit.
And add the lemon juice,
Parmesan cheese.
That will kind of
thicken up the sauce.
Okay,
the gnocchi's ready.
Add to the sauce.
A quick toss.
It's gonna go
onto the plate.
And then
we're gonna garnish it
with some fresh
Parmigiano-Reggiano.
I expect nothing less.
♪♪
Mmm!
That is fantastic!
You can take
a bite of this,
literally put it
right on your tongue
and just press it against
the roof of your mouth
and it just dissolves.
You barely have enough flour
to hold that together.
That's what
makes them good.
And the artichoke
with the mint.
I'm so ripping
that off.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm!
It's dynamite.
MAN: Ricotta and gnocchi.
The consistency,
it's like pillows in my mouth.
Thank you.
The way he works that ricotta
into that dough is great.
Going in the oven --
one sausage and mushroom.
This is the real deal.
FIERI: You got a vibe.
This is half dining room,
half living room,
half your playroom,
and the food shows.
Nice job, chef.
Thank you.
Fantastic.
Watch out for this guy.
Coming up in Miami...
Whoa!
...a family-owned
Colombian spot...
This feels like
celebration food.
...teaching me
a trick or two.
I think I've seen
every culinary technique.
This is 100% new.
You should see
my garage.
My wife bothers me
about it all the time.
Hey. Hey.
I have machines
that I don't have places for.
Hey! Hey!
You got a buddy!
My wife
will kill me, too!
♪♪
So, I'm here on the upper
east side of Miami, Florida,
on Biscayne Boulevard.
And listen --
I love coming to Miami.
It's a melting pot
of all the great flavors.
So, when I hear there's
a family that's knocking out
some delicious Colombian,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Loba.
Bandeja paisa is ready.
This is the number-one spot
to go for Latin food.
Mom, how much
longer on that soup?
The core is Colombian.
But they infuse it
with a Miami vibe.
FIERI: And that Colombian core
is from mom, Libia Sanchez.
I paired
my mom's tradition
with my perception
of how things should change.
What does "Loba" mean?
"She-wolf" in Spanish.
She wolf?
Mm-hmm.
She's totally la loba.
She's totally the loba?
Yeah.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
It's cool to see
the modern mixing
with the traditional food.
MAN:
Lentil croquettes.
WOMAN: You typically don't see
lentils inside of Croquettas.
They're absolutely amazing.
All right,
let's make some lentils.
We start with the water.
You put the lentil in.
And then garlic,
ginger, sweet peppers.
Chicken base.
Onion, red pepper,
green pepper.
Habanero. And how long
do we let the lentils go for?
45 minutes.
And we're gonna strain
out the vegetables.
Just take the lentils,
let those cool. All right, next.
The beet sauce.
And this is Colombian?
No, this is
not Colombian.
Roasted beets.
Here, I got it.
Sweet peppers.
Habanero peppers.
♪♪
And that's it.
Ooh.
[ Laughs ]
We'll form them.
And the egg wash.
We go fry right now?
Yes.
Boom, boom.
All right, sister, let's see it.
♪♪
I love croquettes.
They're crunchy. They're fried.
There's a lot of flavor
in the lentils.
And the guacamole
and the beet -- really good.
Thank you.
That's nice and crispy.
Creamy on the inside,
super flavorful.
It made it appealing
to eat a lentil.
Empanada.
This has
a different speed
from some of the more
glitz and glam
that you normally get
in Miami.
FIERI:
But don't let that fool you.
It turns out
the unassuming she-wolf
used to have a little restaurant
empire before this place.
How many?!
Patacon is a very authentic
Colombian dish.
You take a piece
of the plantain,
and just dip into all the sides
that you like.
All right, mama,
what you got?
Okay.
Onion. oil.
A habanero.
Green pepper.
Now we put the rest.
The cilantro.
She knows this mixer
like playing the violin.
A lot of -- Whoa!
Garlic, salt, and pepper.
Okay.
And how long
are we gonna cook?
20 minutes.
We drop a little water.
Drop a little water.
We mix this.
So, we put
the steak down.
And then we are going
to fry the pork.
You've got a lot going.
Next up?
The patacon.
[ Laughs ]
These are my tools.
I want to see how you do
your green plantains.
They're super tough.
They're hard to peel.
Well, it depends
how you do it.
So, if you go little slices,
it's a lot easier.
Yes.
I can tell you I was
doing it wrong.
Into the fryer?
Yes.
We are going to
prepare the water
that we put
inside the patacon.
Salt in the water.
You put the marinade
that we made.
It's the same one
that we did with the pork
and the rib eye?
Yes.
Now we put
the two green plantains.
So, to keep it
from cracking and falling apart,
she takes it, puts a little
bit of the liquid on it,
and then she uses
this cheesecloth.
I think I've seen
every culinary technique.
This is 100% new.
It's essentially
being mashed
and infusing flavor
through the marinade
that was in the water.
Yes.
And this is gonna fry
like a gigantic tostone?
Yes.
I like it.
Let's go.
The steak first.
Okay.
You put the rice,
guacamole, pico do gallo,
the steak.
[ Whistles ]
The patacon,
then we put the pork,
and we serve
with chimichurri.
One person?
One person.
So, you just break off
a piece like this?
Yes.
Tell me if
I'm doing it wrong.
You do whatever you want to
with your plate.
Do whatever you want to do
with your plate?
This is
my kind of meal.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
That's ridiculous.
Mmm!
What I love about Mexican food
is the tortilla.
But the plantain has got
so much more texture.
You get the chicharone,
and then the herbaceousness
of the chimichurri.
And then you change
to do another bite.
I'll make
a new invention.
It's creative,
it's very fulfilling.
This feels like
celebration food.
Thank you.
The patacon.
It's really hard to make,
and they always make it
really good here.
The first time we that
ever shot in Little Havana
in Miami was
at David's place.
How do you say it?
La Camaronera.
Exactly. That easy.
You look at this.
You've got tostones.
Yeah, no, these things
look like they're on steroids.
That's crazy.
When you walk in,
you just feel like,
yeah, you're
at the right place.
Fantastic.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
♪♪
So, was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives.
♪♪
You can do it, Rocky.
[ Laughs ]
[ As Rocky ] Adrian!
[ Laughter ]