Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ah hah!
...we're digging into dishes...
I'd eat
that whole thing.
...rolling in
some dynamite dough...
Works for me.
...like in Arizona...
Look at that bun.
...a stuffed
Hawaiian specialty...
Delicious meat thing!
...along with
a fresh Italian spin.
That's ridiculous.
Plus, decadent donuts
in Miami...
I mean, who are we kidding here?
This is over the top.
FIERI:
...creatively sweet...
Just so you know, we're gonna
have to push the car home.
...and surprisingly savory.
This changes the fried
chicken sandwich game.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Mesa, Arizona,
and I'm landlocked.
If you want to take a vacation,
you say,
"Gosh, I'd really like
to go to Hawaii,
but I can't afford it,
I don't have the time."
But you're craving the food.
Well, don't worry,
ladies and gentlemen.
I hear there's a place
that will transport you,
on a plate,
right back to the islands.
This is Aloha Kitchen.
♪♪
Fried salmon in
a couple more minutes.
Everything is infused
with a lot of flavor.
Got a katsu bulgogi with toss.
Makes you feel like
you're in Hawaii.
FIERI: An Hawaiian native,
Lynn Tso and her husband, Ray,
have been serving up
island staples
like lunch plates
and marinated meats
to the people of the desert
for more than two decades.
What are you two doing
in Arizona?
I came here
as a graduate student
in public health
nutrition.
Okay.
What about you?
-I'm just following.
-He's just following.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: But then, back in '86,
Lynn was looking
for a career change,
which led to
opening this place.
I pulled out
my food service textbook,
and I read it
cover to cover.
So, you took what you knew
how to cook,
which you grew up on,
and then you applied
the principles of food service
and made the magic happen?
Yes.
Every time I come and eat here,
it makes me want to go there.
SERVER:
I have a couple of manapuas.
The manapuas are awesome.
WOMAN: It's a stuffed,
steamed pork bun.
Used to eat that all the
time growing up in Hawaii.
All right, let's go.
First,
we're gonna use sugar.
A bunch of it.
And then some yeast.
Dry active.
Some warm water.
And let that bloom.
Then we're gonna
put in the flour.
Flour power.
Too short for this.
I got you.
Oh! Oh!
Between the two of us, we
might get half of it in here.
We'll get most of it in.
[ Laughs ]
And 15 minutes?
15 minutes.
The dough is done.
Proofs for
about 20 minutes.
And how do we say this,
again?
Manapua. The Chinese
brought it over.
They would have Chinese men
carrying the pole across
their shoulders,
and they would call out,
"Mea 'ono pua'a."
"Mea" is "thing,"
"'ono" is "delicious,"
"pua'a" is
"meat" or "pork."
Delicious meat thing?
Yeah.
Delicious meat thing!
Manapua!
We're gonna make the marinade,
the char siu marinade.
Okay, so, pork shoulder,
bone out.
Right. Sugar, soy sauce,
red food coloring.
So, I made char siu -- I made
it with the food coloring
and I made it
without the food coloring
and did a tasting
with my friends.
10 to 1, they liked
the red one versus...
Isn't that amazing?
The red bark makes
all the difference.
Oyster sauce, hoisin,
cooking wine.
Okay.
We're gonna marinate it
overnight.
How long are we gonna
cook it?
For about an hour, at 350.
Once it's done,
we cube it up?
Yes.
Works for me.
Works for you? Good.
Gravy's next?
Yes.
Soy sauce, oyster sauce,
sugar, water,
little bit of black pepper,
green onion, sesame oil.
Bring it to a simmer.
Cornstarch and water.
Tighten it up.
All right.
Pour the sauce
over the meat.
Now we're gonna
put it together.
We've got
the proofed dough.
Then you make a cup,
take a spoonful,
and then
pinch it together.
Okay, we're gonna
proof them again,
and how long
do they steam?
They steam for
about 15 to 20 minutes.
All right,
let's see it.
Those are huge!
Look at that bun!
♪♪
Mmm.
The bun is
so tender and light,
and then the meat filling's
got a nice little salt
and a little funk.
That is so good.
Char siu itself is great.
It's nice and tender.
And pork butt's the
exact one you want to use.
The gravy that we made --
that's the kicker.
It's sweet, it's meaty,
it's luxurious.
That's one of the best
I've ever had.
You're a superstar.
Two manapuas -- pick up.
The sweet bread
and the filling together
just make an amazing
combination.
Anytime I meet someone
from the island,
I always ask them, "Have you
been to the Aloha Kitchen?"
Chopping short ribs.
When you walk through the
door, does it take you home?
Oh, yeah. It's as if
we're going home.
FIERI:
And this island-inspired
Korean barbecue
is like another
culinary plane ticket.
Your kalbi ribs.
Break down the kalbi rib
for me. What do you think?
Absolutely excellent.
Falls apart in your mouth.
Everybody knows short ribs
when they're all together
and you roast them
low and slow,
but this is
the Korean style?
Yes.
You have the butcher
cut them really thin.
1/3 of an inch?
-Yeah.
Let's make the marinade.
We have soy sauce,
sugar, brown sugar,
vegetable oil,
cooking wine, sesame oil,
fresh garlic,
and sesame seeds.
Mix it all together,
pour it over the top.
Marinate it
3 to 4 hours.
All right.
Let's grill them.
Look at those --
gorgeous.
Oh, they're delicious.
It comes with
two scoops of steamed rice,
a green salad
or a potato mac salad.
Potato mac?
That's a normal order?
That's it.
-All of this?
-All of this.
Okay. There you go.
♪♪
It's like meat candy.
Mmm.
I love Korean food.
This is as good,
if not better,
than most
that I've ever had.
I've been on the island.
I've eaten at these
funky little joints.
I've had this food.
This is authentic.
It's outstanding.
I mean, like, lights out.
You're a dangerous woman.
I would eat that
and eat that...
And eat that.
...and eat that.
So good.
MAN: Very tender ribs that
fall right off the bone.
Great grill taste to it.
It reminds me
of being back home,
having kalbi on the beach.
Kalua pork plate ready.
Good portions, good size,
and it's always delicious.
We tell everybody
about this place.
The story is awesome.
You're the real deal.
I want you to send some of this
to me to my house.
[ Laughs ]
Nice job.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, I'm headed a
couple hours south, to Tucson...
Okay, there we go.
...for a hearty
Italian sandwich...
It's a good-looking bite.
...and a calzone
that lets you grip the dip.
You'll see what I mean.
This is dangerous, bro.
♪♪
So, I'm here on the northeast
side of Tucson, Arizona,
in a -- wait for it.
Exactly -- in a strip mall.
Anyhow, the point is, I'm
here to check out a joint
where this husband-and-wife
team, they're going
to the beat of their own drum,
doing it their own way.
This is Renee's Organic Oven.
♪♪
Yucatan ready in the window!
I would describe Renee's
as home-cooked food.
Spaghetti in there.
I can definitely taste
the freshness.
Got a vegan pesto pastaless
dish in the window!
MAN: It brings meat-eaters,
vegetarians, vegans.
You can always find
something for everybody.
FIERI:
And it's all dished up with love
by high school sweethearts
Renee and Steve Kreager.
Give me
the rundown here.
If we're in the elevator
and you said,
"Hey, you're the guy
that does
'Drivers, Divers,
and Dine-Ins'" --
Whatever you call it.
'Cause no one's ever
said it to me that way.
We are a local spot that
focuses on community.
So we're looking at things
that are approachable,
that have a lot of detail
to them.
How does it materialize
into a menu item?
It's a pizza.
Okay. There we go.
We went up and down
like eight times
in the elevator
to get the answer.
But pizza's
the main foundation here?
That's what we started it
with, and then we've expanded.
WOMAN: It's funny to me that
they call it a pizza joint,
because there's so much
more than pizza here.
And a Tailored Tony.
The Tailored Tony, it's like
a home-cooked spaghetti sauce
with some crusty focaccia bread
that's, like, soft in the
middle, crunchy on the outside.
So what are we making?
Today, we're making our dough
for our homemade focaccia.
All right, so,
break it down for me.
We just add our water,
flour, organic sugar,
simple yeast,
extra virgin olive oil.
And this is gonna mix
up for, what -- 10 minutes?
Yep.
And it proofs for a day?
So, you get all that great
yeasty flavor.
So, we hit a drizzle
of olive oil on there.
Give us a really nice crust
on the bottom.
Little bit of marjoram.
Oregano, too.
Onion granules, and a
salt-and-pepper blend.
So, then, we got to press out
the dough to fit the ka-pan.
You add extra syllables in.
I like it. You're making
your own language.
Oh, we make up
our own stuff here.
You ever heard
of a wheel knife?
-A wheel knife?
-Yeah.
-It's got to be a pizza cutter.
-Yeah. Good job.
Extra virgin olive oil.
We're gonna do
the same thing on the top.
Just a repeat.
Are we gonna
let this proof again
with all of the herbs
and the giddy-up on there?
Yeah, it doubles in size,
so we wrap it
with the wrap master
and get it nice and...
With the wrap master?
Yeah, it's not one busting
flows or anything.
It's just
the plastic puller.
Ah hah! His point.
That was good.
What temp are we gonna
cook it at in the oven?
Pizza oven, 525.
Next up?
For the whole house, we do
a marinara in all the stuff --
our spaghetti
and everything like that.
But we make this
for our meat sauce, too.
So, we're gonna
ground some beef.
Onions, basil, garlic.
Minced garlic, yeah.
House-milled pepper.
Get it
nice and blended up.
And add it to
ground tomatoes.
Balsamic vinegar,
red wine vinegar,
and extra virgin olive oil.
Now it's ready
for our cooked meat.
Okay.
After the focaccia's
cooled off,
we put it facedown
in the oven to toast.
Our house meat sauce
that we've made up.
Are we both having one,
or is that
the normal amount
you put on there?
-That's the normal amount.
-That's ridiculous.
A little provolone.
Red bell peppers, roasted,
put it on some paper.
Back in the oven.
Until it's nice and toasted
and melted and looking good.
A little fresh basil
when it comes out.
It's ready to go.
So, it's an open-faced,
mature sloppy joe.
Essentially, yeah.
And a little Caesar
here on the side?
House dressing,
homemade croutons.
I love Caesar dressing.
It's a good-looking bite.
♪♪
Really nice, light focaccia --
not too heavy, not too dense.
I like
the salty provolone.
But the kicker
on the whole thing --
those roasted
red bells, man.
That's really singing
through, that nice sweetness.
Just a simple tomato sauce,
using really good --
I mean, if you're gonna make it
that simple, you got to use
really dynamite ingredients
that shine through.
Yeah.
-Excellent.
-Thank you very much.
Tailored Tony with Caesar salad.
The homemade focaccia is
really delicious.
The sauce has a really, really
full-body tomato flavor.
-Explosion in my mouth.
-Pretty gangster.
MAN: That Alfredo drop
with the chicken...
It's like it's made from your
own kitchen -- fresh, organic.
Everything's organic?
As we go, we've been evolving
it and picking up more.
We're the first ones
bringing in the flour
and the ground tomatoes and
the paste that was organic.
I had to buy them
pallets at a time.
Really?
STEVE: We got a spaghetti, add
meatballs on that one.
WOMAN: Everything is great.
Everything is.
You don't, like,
feel bad after the meal.
You know, you actually feel
a lot better.
So, I'm gonna eat this, take
a small nap, I'll be back.
All right.
Sounds good.
FIERI: And then I'll be ready
for round 2,
digging into a hearty
calzone that screams "comfort."
Spinach dip calzones
for you.
It's like a burst
of gooey happiness.
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back. I just had
a little sandwich nap,
and we're hanging out
at Renee's Organic Oven
here in Tucson, Arizona.
Renee's feels like your
classic Italian restaurant,
but it's definitely not.
The quality
of the ingredients is
by far, in Tucson,
one of the best.
-What are we making next?
-Our spinach dip calzone.
Calzone dipped
into the spinach?
No. Homemade spinach dip
is inside the calzone.
The calzone has a gooey
cheese, roasted chilies,
chicken, all wrapped
in a flaky crust.
We're making our hoos --
house-made chicken.
We're gonna make
the hoos-made.
The hoos-made chicken.
[ Scottish accent ]
Oh, yes, we are.
It's garlic salt, parsley,
onion granules,
Spanish paprika,
some oregano.
[ Normal voice ]
All right.
A little chicken broth
in there.
Little whisk here, make it
like a nice little paste.
My baby whisk.
A little whisk with
a little whisk.
Yeah, it makes sense
in my head.
[which]
Whisk way do you do it?
[ Laughs ]
Pour it
all over the chicken.
And we're gonna roast
that off in the oven?
12 minutes and then we flip
it, another 12 minutes.
Now we're gonna make the dip
that's not gonna be a dip.
Right. It's gonna be a
filling for the calzone.
I was bored one day at work,
told the driver to go
get some cream cheese.
He's like, "I love cream cheese.
What are you doing?"
I said, "I'm gonna make
something good. Go get it
and bring it back."
What does he think you're
doing with cream cheese? You
gonna fix a hole in the wall?
You could probably.
"What are you gonna do
with that cream cheese?
You gonna make
rocket fuel?"
Spinach,
chopped-up artichokes,
some diced organic tomatoes,
mozzarella,
shredded Parmesan,
some minced garlic,
the salt-and-pepper blend.
Get a big ol' block
of cream cheese.
So, you're gonna
mix this by hand?
Oh, yeah.
All right, so, that mixes
together, you portion it out.
Our dough is up
and proofed.
It's time to bust out
the wheel knife --
[real]
as opposed
to the fake knife.
You're saying "wheel"
as in "real."
No,
like a wheel on a car.
Oh, like...
[ Whistling ]
Yeah.
Good ol' hefty portion of
spinach dip.
Some of our diced chicken
that we have.
And some
roasted hatch chilies.
Yup. Just gonna shred
those by hand.
Dude, shreddin'.
Mozzarella -- do a little
fold-over and just push down.
Get my little
trusty wheel knife here.
Wheel knife!
Get a little clean edge.
Did you just give a little
hole to the top of that?
Yeah.
You don't put
that little slit there,
all the steam builds inside,
it domes up,
then there's no moisture
inside of that dome.
That gets really hard
and crispy and crunchy,
and it doesn't have that nice
chewy texture that you want.
This goes in the oven --
12 minutes, 525.
Just give a little cut,
and this comes out with
a side of marinara.
I like the way you woll
with the wheel knife.
All right.
♪♪
So, it's a cross between the
best jalapeño popper you had,
a gigantic pierogi, and some
crazy chicken sandwich --
all put together in one.
You got
dynamite balance
between the cream cheese
with the mozzarella,
so it's not super gooey,
tacky, thick.
I love the hatch chili
in there.
And the dynamite dough, all
of that playing together...
This is dangerous, bro.
-Thank you very much.
-I mean, really tasty.
-Thank you.
STEVE: Spinach dip calzone.
WOMAN: The chicken inside
is a really nice touch --
adds a lot to the flavor.
All the ingredients are fresh,
so I can taste everything.
Pizza roll.
Their beer list
is always great, too.
Their beard list?
Their beer. Beer.
Not "beard," but "beer."
I was gonna say,
"The beard list?"
If you come in
for the beard list...
I look like a guy that would.
[ Laughs ]
Another 12-inch sausage,
peppers.
It's an everything kind of
place -- everything is great.
My mouth waters
when I walk in the door.
-Congratulations.
-All right.
Watch out for this guy.
Seriously --
he carries a wheel knife.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, an artisan
donut shop in Miami...
All right. Let's get down
to the nitty-gritty.
...creating mouthwatering
masterpieces...
I don't like sweets.
I'd eat that whole thing.
...with a fried chicken
chaser.
Whoa, whoa!
That's right.
♪♪
We're hanging out
at Renee's Organic Oven
here in Tucson, Arizona.
What are you doing?
Were you having
a nap, too?
Yeah.
I was zoning out.
Okay. It's all right.
It's your place.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Miami, with
one of my favorite chefs,
Chef Richard Hales from
Black Brick and Sakaya Kitchen.
All right, dude,
where are we in Miami?
We're at what they call
the soaseta.
-What does that mean?
-It means "Southwest."
Okay. And what kind of food
do you find down in the soaseta?
Venezuelan, Cuban,
Colombian.
Okay, so, is it weird
that I'm taking you
to a gourmet donut shop?
Not at all, brother.
They're blowing up in Miami.
Fantastic.
But is this place legit?
I hear it is. This is
Mojo Donuts & Fried Chicken.
Death by Chocolate up!
Nobody has donuts like Mojo.
The Deco Delight with
strawberries and blueberries.
It's a sea of beautiful
colors and deliciousness.
These are all
handmade donuts?
Every single one.
FIERI: 'Cause it's the passion
of owner Jimmy Piedrahita.
We do it the way when
donuts were first started --
hand-rolled, hand-cut.
It's even fried
with the chopsticks,
the way they were
back in the day.
FIERI:
But back in the day, they didn't
make sandwiches out of them.
Here's your
chicken brulee sandwich.
There's chicken in a donut.
With the bacon, the cheese --
it's an incredible sandwich.
Okay, I want to try
chicken and donut.
Best thing we could go with
is our chicken brulee sandwich.
All right,
so, how do we get started?
With our dough.
Water. This is
our donut mix.
Next, we add in
some instant yeast.
As soon as it starts
running, I'm gonna add
the rest of the water.
What's the total
mixing time?
6 to 7 minutes.
So, this big,
gigantic monster...
-Just smell the yeast.
-Right off the bat.
I know nothing about making
donuts, by the way.
Cut them out.
Ho!
Pop them out.
We're getting
the center-cut donut.
I love it.
These will go next
into a proof box,
and they'll rise up.
-Then we fry?
-Yep.
-350?
-365 -- palm oil.
-Palm oil?
-Yep.
The oil actually
gets absorbed,
and even after
we pull it out,
it's still cooking because
the oil is absorbed in there.
Now, chicken tenders.
And our marinade.
Hit it.
Take our sour orange,
pepper, salt, garlic.
So, these are gonna get
12-hour marinade,
and then what are we going
to be battering these in?
Our dry breading, and then
we put it into our wet.
For me, it's the sort of
updated version
of chicken and waffles.
-I got you.
All right, let's fry these up
and build this brulee donut.
Okay. Wet the shell,
nice sugar.
-All over it?
-All over it.
Then, we start
caramelizing the shell.
That's culinary napalm
right there.
It is.
We want it to have that
crispy outside texture.
We put in
the tenderloin.
We get a mild Wisconsin
cheddar cheese.
Okay.
A little bit
of seasoning in it.
-Oh, my goodness.
-Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
That's right.
And we make sure we put on
plenty of bacon.
You've got problems.
[ Laughter ]
Our chicken brulee sandwich
is born.
All right. Let's get down
to the nitty-gritty.
♪♪
From the beginning,
I thought,
"Fried chicken
in a donut -- okay."
But it's really
a lot more complex.
That's really good.
I mean, who are we kidding here?
This is over the top.
Salty, sweet,
something fried in there.
You have
that ooey-gooey cheese
that just, like, equalizes
everything together.
Cheese sauce is
a kicker.
Yeah.
And the yeasty donut.
Mm-hmm.
The crunch of the caramel
brulee, the smoky bacon...
I mean, this has really
got some legitimate
textures and flavors.
This changes the fried
chicken sandwich game.
Order up!
The chicken brulee sandwich
is delicious --
a perfect bite of goodness.
You ever heard of anything
like that?
Not really,
but it's amazing.
It's very creative what
they put on the donuts.
Any donut beyond your
wildest dreams, they have.
PIEDRAHITA: We have
over 200 original recipes.
-Really?
-Yes, sir.
Banana cream pie,
holy cannoli.
What's the
number-one-selling donut?
Our abuelita donut.
Here's your abuelita.
Once you bite into it and you
get to the arroz con leche,
it's like a bunch of
flavors all put together.
Many people here in Miami,
it reminds them of their
grandmother's rice pudding.
And this is
a 100-year-old recipe?
It is. It was
handed down to us.
Take me into it.
Start off with whole
milk, a whole lime peel.
Got it.
Vanilla extract,
cinnamon root.
What type of rice?
Short-grain
Valencian rice.
Let that simmer for
about an hour and a half,
seal it up for a little
bit, and let it absorb.
And then what's
gonna happen?
We add a little more of
that vanilla extract,
evaporated milk,
whole stick of butter.
Sugar.
-Whoa.
Sweetened condensed milk.
That little bit of salt?
Yup. A little bit
more cinnamon.
All this cooks down, and
then we're gonna pipe this
into one
of the shell donuts?
That is correct.
So, this is strictly just for
the donut-injection program?
Yup.
The Thunder Pumper 9000.
Thunder Pumper 9000.
We take our cinnamon sugar
shells...
[ Whirring ]
And now...
-They're not done yet?
They're not done yet.
We take our dulce de leche.
Just so you know, we're gonna
have to push the car home.
Yes.
Take some powdered sugar.
Now...it's ready.
[ Laughing ] My doctor doesn't
see this episode.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
[ Muffled ]
Do I have any there?
-Nope. Nothing. Nothing.
-You're good.
It feels like
there's something.
-No. No, no. No, no.
-No.
You sure?!
-Positive.
-Tiny bit.
[ Laughing ]
Now there's a little...
I don't like sweets.
I'd eat that whole thing.
Awesome.
The shell donut has a
good amount of yeast to it
and isn't too naturally sweet,
so you're getting
a little bit of that savory
contrast right off the bat.
So then when you do hit it
with all your craziness,
it's just not
a sugar overload.
You know, it takes
a chef's touch
to sort of, like,
balance that,
not making the arroz con leche
too sweet.
-It's a dangerous donut.
-It is.
Abuelitas ready to go.
It's sweet and creamy.
It reminds me
of my country -- Cuba.
JIMMY:
One Mojo specialty combo.
If Heaven had a flavor,
it'd be Mojo Donuts.
You've really put
some culinary behind it.
Well done, buddy.
-Thank you so much.
-Let's go push the car.
-Let's go.
So, that's it for this road
trip, but don't worry.
We got plenty more joints to
find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I'm not saying
over here or here,
but, like, right here it feels
like there's something.
No?
You can trust me.
He's such a good friend!
[ Laughter ]