Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I feel a food coma coming on.
It's seafood
and savory smorgasbord.
Magic's about to happen.
Like in a classic fish house
in North Carolina...
You've kept it old-school
and you've done it great.
...a Bosnian joint
keeping it real in Tucson...
Ooh.
Fantastic.
...and in Lansing, Michigan...
This, right here,
I'm excited for.
...a fresh
and funky food truck...
It's gonna be crazy.
I can already tell you.
...driving off the rails
when it comes to the menu.
It's one of the most unique food
truck item that I've ever seen.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
I got to tell you,
food truck nation,
full steam ahead
into Flavortown.
I'm on the the outskirts
of East Lansing, Michigan,
about a mile
from Michigan State,
to check out a husband and wife
team that's got a food truck.
Now the menu sounds simple, but
the flavors and techniques --
super complex.
You won't forget this.
This is The Purple Carrot.
♪♪
SANTUCCI:
Crispy chicken for Kyle!
Everything looks so good.
Yeah, everything.
Always on point.
Corn quiche for Tony.
Everything is done
with creativity.
FIERI:
Which is a passion husband
and wife team
Tony Maiale and Nina Santucci
brought back to her
Michigan hometown
after they met working
in the Philly food scene.
We do everything
from scratch.
Everything's farm-to-table
here -- meats, cheeses, produce.
And even seafood.
Your shrimp burger.
I'm eating the shrimp burger.
It's delicious.
It is made with the best
shrimp you can find.
From the local shrimp farmer.
So, on this little,
mini hot plate,
we're gonna get it
hot enough to make food?
Yes, absolutely.
Oh, I got to see this.
We're gonna start
with a little oil,
and a sofrito consists of some
onions, carrots, some celery.
Okay.
Salt, a little pepper
and a little sugar
to bring out natural
sweetness of all vegetables.
Now where did you learn
to cook?
Uh, I went to Pennsylvania
Culinary in Pittsburgh.
Is that where you're from?
Philadelphia, I'm from.
Born and raised.
Love Philly.
Shout-out.
What's up, Philly?
We'll add some bay leaf,
parsley, chives,
tarragon, dill,
Spanish paprika.
Sweat all this down.
Let it cool?
Yep.
So these are
the beautiful shrimp.
I mean, that's too pretty
to make into a patty.
We'll peel these right up.
Okay.
They're gonna get thrown
in the food processor.
The cooked sofrito, and now,
we're gonna buzz it up.
How do you get it
to stick together?
The tackiness of the shrimp
kind of --
See?
So, it's not bad once in a while
to be a little tacky.
[ Boing! ]
Got some nice chunks
in there still.
You're all mixed up.
Yeah, but I'm working
through it, in therapy.
We're just gonna add some salt,
a little bit of pepper,
and again,
a little bit of sugar.
You and your sugar.
And then we'll just
patty them up.
That's the shrimp cake
you always wanted.
No filla.
All thrilla.
So, next step, we're gonna make
the apple cabbage slaw.
Start with extra
virgin olive oil,
sherry maple vinegar,
fresh-chopped thyme,
season with a little --
Guess what?
Salt, pepper and...
BOTH: Sugar.
Whisk that up,
add our shredded cabbage.
And then the fun part,
slicing the apples.
You guys really do get
some awesome produce.
We do.
I mean, with Michigan around,
they're actually second
behind California
for diversity of produce.
Really?
Add some butter to the flat top,
the shrimp burger,
add the bun and toast it up.
We'll top it off with some
hot sauce aioli, patty, slaw,
finish it with the bun.
Well done.
Mmm.
The depth of the flavor inside
of that patty is ridiculous.
Not being bound by any filler,
that's really the key.
Acid from the cabbage,
and you get a little extra fat
coming in from the aioli.
When you can get this kind
of food in a food truck, boy,
that's a gift.
Mmm.
Right there.
Shrimp burger for Kyle!
Very thick, very juicy.
I could go and buy shrimp
from the same farm they use
in Mason, Michigan, but it's not
gonna taste like this.
WOMAN:
We have a lot of local farms.
We'll see that food coming
out of the food truck.
In the winter, since it's
a more rooted-vegetable season,
they would probably go for
carrots, beets, radishes.
What happens
when it's snowing?
They're still rolling.
Rain, snow...
Part food truck,
part mail man.
MAN: On any given day, you might
want something different.
It's usually here.
SANTUCCI:
Mash bites for Melissa!
I love the mash bites.
They're fried on the outside,
they're gooey on the inside,
and they like pop in your mouth.
So, it's almost like
a mozzarella stick,
but with mashed potatoes.
No cheese. It tastes like
there's cheese in it.
No cheese?
First thing we'll do is, we'll
just bloom this sheet gelatin.
Let that sit for
a couple minutes.
So now we're gonna make butter
cream sauce for the mash.
We will add to the pot
the cream and the butter.
We'll let that simmer
probably about an hour or so,
while you're baking
your potatoes.
So these are Butterballs?
Yeah, a local potato grown
in Holland, Michigan.
Yeah, that's right.
Where you from?
Holland, Michigan.
Good potato.
So the gelatin's ready.
It is a messy process.
Squeeze out the extra liquid.
Into the reduction.
Okay.
We'll just add the cream
and the potatoes to the blender.
What I always love
is filling up a mixer
to the top
with a hot liquid.
I'll be over here.
You just want to make sure
that it's all pureed.
You've got some anger
issues, don't you?
No.
So we'll add some salt to this
and just a little bit of sugar.
You and the sugar thing.
Lay this on the sheet tray.
I love this.
You know I'm ripping this off?
That's fine.
And that gelatin
is going to set up.
This, right here,
I'm excited for.
So look at that.
That's firm like you've been
going to the gym.
[ Chuckles ]
We'll just kind of pop it
right out of there.
It's like a potato bath mat.
Now we'll just cut them
down into strips.
-That small, huh?
-Oh, yeah, that small.
Yeah.
Toss these right there
in the flour.
They look like little
mozzarella balls.
It's gonna be crazy.
I can already tell you.
Egg wash.
We'll panko-batter it.
Fry to golden brown.
Magic's about to happen.
Just a little garnish.
A sorrel mix with a little
borage and some cress.
The fact that it's not cheese
is ridiculous.
That's way out there.
It's creative, it's unique.
And it's executed perfectly.
Mash bites for Melissa.
It's like that perfect mix
of crunchy and creamy.
It's one of the most unique food
truck items I've ever seen.
It just make you want
to come back again,
not only for the food, but just
to see their smiling faces.
-Excellent job, Chef.
-Thank you.
This guy's killin' it.
Thi--This, huh?
There, there, all right.
Hit it in slo-mo.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
FIERI: Up next, a one-of-a-kind
chef in Tucson...
Uh, this is not
his first rodeo.
...sharing the flavors
of Eastern Europe...
What you get flavor-wise
is outrageous.
...along with his amazing story.
From my heart.
You're a good man, Chef.
♪♪
Let's see it.
Right here, right now, "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Drive" --
Okay, see?
So, I still got a job.
I still got a job.
You still got a job.
♪♪
So I'm here in central
Tucson, Arizona,
about 15 minutes away
from the University of Arizona.
And, quite frankly,
ladies and gentlemen,
that's all you need to know.
Because what's about to happen
in this little mini-mart,
office park, whatever you
want to call it,
is a place that's
gonna culinarily
teleport you to Bosnia.
Ladies and gentlemen,
no passports necessary.
This is Chef Alisah's.
♪♪
Bosnian pork.
Everybody that comes in here
just absolutely loves it.
We have our beef
with mushroom sauce.
It is the best comfort food
you have ever eaten.
Dinstani kupus.
The chef is a very
special person.
He hasn't had an easy path.
FIERI:
Ahmet Alisah's path started
as he grew up cooking
in his mom's restaurant.
But the Bosnian war
in the early '90s
ended up shattering his family.
International goodwill landed
his family in Tucson.
But it took him years
of recovery
to be able to work again.
And finally, after 10 years,
we open this restaurant --
me, my wife, and my son.
And they brought the best
traditions of their country
to Southern Arizona.
Order of cevapi.
Bosnian sausages.
MAN: Thank you.
Bosnian sausages are the staple
of this restaurant.
It feels like you're
walking down
that cobblestone street
in Bosnia.
It just feels like home.
Cevapi, I'm not kidding you,
when I was in Croatia,
it was one of the best
things I had when I went.
Okay,
what are we gonna make?
We make fresh, soft bread
they call lepinja in Bosnia.
And this is gonna go
with the cevapi?
Exactly.
Water, flour...
-Salt and yeast.
-That's it.
Very simple recipe.
Yes.
I will mix it
about five minutes.
People love it.
He's his own pitch man.
So we're gonna form these up
with the semolina on the bottom.
These are gonna go
in the oven, what temperature?
500 degrees,
about 10 minutes.
And now we make the cevapi.
Now we make cevapi.
What do we got here, Chef?
We got beef chuck rolls.
Okay.
So we take the chuck,
we break it down.
This is a pretty rustic,
traditional dish,
but if done the right way
with simple ingredients,
you're gonna get
an outstanding flavor.
-Yes.
-So now we season.
Yes.
Season.
Salt.
Pepper.
And baking soda.
Mix it up.
I mix with hands.
Then we'll grind it.
Mix it with some water.
Two eggs and mineral water.
Binds it together and makes it
a little bit lighter.
Exactly.
We put in the fridge overnight.
And then we'll put it through
the machine to make the sausage.
I put in ground beef.
No casing.
Exactly.
So he sees the measurement
come out as long as his hand is,
and then he cleans it up
there with the finger.
Yes.
Oh, this is not
his first rodeo.
People love it.
Look at that.
3,000 every 10 days.
Wow.
Now we're gonna take this,
on the grill, with the bread.
Boy, if I didn't live on this
when I was in Croatia.
Now butter this time?
Yes.
And they've got to
have the onions.
Look at the crust on that.
Ooh.
And bread.
And please join.
I tell you from my heart.
You're a good man, Chef.
So, a little tzatziki,
a little bit of the onion,
a piece of the cevapi.
Mmm.
We can count all the ingredients
in this dish on one hand.
But what you get,
flavor-wise, is outrageous.
Oh!
Seasoned correctly,
a little tzatziki sauce,
a little white onion,
and then some of this
fantastic bread --
simple yeast bread.
Ooh.
Fantastic.
Cevapi.
WOMAN: The bread is really good.
It almost reminds me of like
a thicker pita bread.
The sausage is perfectly crisp.
WOMAN #2: It's a lot of really
good flavor.
Just nothing like
it here in Tucson.
Well, I think you watch it,
'cause you come in here,
you could have cevapi
till you drop.
Whoa.
[ Laughter ]
Bread is ready, you know?
I take from grill.
Chef Alisah's wonderful.
He's always on the floor
greeting customers.
Absolutely the hardest working
guy I've ever met in my life.
What time do you get up
in the morning, Alisah?
About 6:30 a.m., and I go home
about middle night.
-About middle night?
-Yes.
If I sleep,
I dream about food.
You can see him so filled
with pride and joy of life,
and it's really infectious.
So, here's the deal.
You want to come back and hang
out at the table with Alisah?
I do.
I want more.
FIERI:
Especially when it's this
real-deal meal.
We have our goulash.
MAN: Goulash -- I've had it in
a number of different countries.
The best I've ever eaten.
There's more happening.
See you in a bit.
[ Laughs ]
The house Alisah.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're hanging out in Tucson,
Arizona, at Chef Alisah's,
a Bosnian joint
run by refugee
Ahmet Alisah
and his family.
Shish kebab.
The food is
absolutely incredible.
He does everything
with such authenticity.
So, he hasn't taken Bosnian
food and Americanized it?
No.
WOMAN: I've been to Sarajevo
several times,
and it rivals anything
that I've eaten.
ALISAH: Bosnian goulash.
It's a braised beef
in a red sauce.
WOMAN: Kind of similar to like
a Southern brisket,
with how tender the meat is,
but it's our version.
Goulash.
Chef Alisah's style.
Of course.
We put olive oil in,
fresh onion, cut,
cubed beef chuck roast.
Now we put tomato sauce,
tomato past,
you know, paprika,
Spanish style.
Black pepper,
parsley, dried.
Vegeta.
That's veggie base.
Exactly.
And water.
And how long are we gonna
let that cook, Chef?
Almost 3 hours,
and it will be perfect.
Tender?
-Tender.
-Fantastic.
Now we make homemade
cabbage salad, Bosnian style.
Okay.
We take fresh cabbage,
salt, vinegar,
olive oil, and black pepper.
And now, I mix with my hand.
Strong?
Strong like bull.
-Exactly.
-Okay.
♪♪
And that's the slaw?
That's it.
Goulash.
Goulash is ready.
I feel a food coma coming on.
You know, it's nice.
You've got to love this guy.
I'm not kidding you.
And green parsley.
And please try.
When I tell you tender...
if you look at this meat
the wrong way,
it will fall apart.
Mmm.
Really a lot deeper and richer
than most goulash that I've had,
but not heavy.
The paprika balances nice.
The sauce is fantastic.
This big, bold sauce that
comes out of this chuck roll.
But I want you to think
about the best beef stew
you ever had
and knock it up a notch.
Take a little bite of that
slaw and cleanse that palate.
And you're right back in it.
Outrageous.
-The goulash.
-Thank you.
Oh, it melts in your mouth.
It is so tender.
This is the best.
I tell people if they want
to know what savory is...
He's the salt
and the savory.
-He is.
-It's true.
Surprise plate for two people.
He loves what he does,
and it really shines
through in the food.
Fantastic.
This is a great
experience for people.
My pleasure.
Very easy to drive
by this place.
You got to slow down to find
Chef Alisah's.
Exactly.
But when you find it,
you're home.
-Thank you.
-I'm coming back.
Thank you very much.
♪♪
FIERI: Comin' up, a standout
seafood spot
in Wilmington,
North Carolina...
That's it!
That's it.
...frying up the fish...
Holy moly.
...plating up the puppies...
That's why you're
the hush puppy king.
...and churning out the chowder.
Now, if you could just
get it like that,
in a rotating shovel
of spoons in my face...
♪♪
I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina,
and I got to be honest
with my "Triple D" family.
I've taken you to some places
where the name hasn't
really matched the menu.
I took you to Bub and Pop's.
What'd I give you?
Sub sandwiches.
I took you to the Tattooed Moose
and gave you a duck
confit club sandwich.
Well, today, I'm gonna
make it super easy.
I'm gonna take you to a place,
and if you can't figure out
what they're serving,
you're not allowed to come.
This is Something Fishy.
♪♪
Grilled mahi.
Absolutely the best
seafood around.
WAITRESS:
Shrimp and flounder.
I grew up here, and this
is just what we eat.
Crab cake up.
This has always been our number-
one choice for fried seafood.
FIERI:
And in this coastal community,
that's high praise for owner
Ricky Hobbs and
his old-school fish fry.
When I think of North
Carolina and I think
of being a little kid
and coming to Morehead City,
there were little
fish shacks like this.
HOBBS:
This was a convenience store.
Really?
This came available
and I said, "You know,
that'd be a really good place
to put a restaurant."
And he was right,
because that was back in '91.
And today, they're still serving
up their seafood staples.
Clam chowder up.
Clam chowder's really creamy,
good, soft potatoes in it.
There are clams
in every single spoonful.
It's awesome.
What are we making?
-Clam chowder.
-Straight forward.
Straight forward.
Take us on a path.
First, we'll put some butter
in, celery, onion, bacon.
A little flour, so we're
gonna build our roux.
Make a roux.
Pepper, salt, clam juice,
whole milk, half and half,
some spring onions,
our clams, some Old Bay.
Why does the way he says
Old Bay sound cooler
than the way I say it?
Old Bay.
I'm from the South.
I'd -- See, the whole time, I'd
say Montana, but you're right.
Put potatoes in.
So, let that heat up.
And what do we
serve that with?
Hush puppies.
Of course we do.
That was a dumb question.
You're doing seafood,
you've got to do hush puppies.
Okay.
Corn meal, self-rising flour,
dried onion,
baking powder, salt,
black pepper, we've got sugar.
You've got that little
kiss of the sweet.
I try to give it a whole lot.
A whole lot of kisses
of sweet?
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
Hot water.
So this is gonna get all mixed
up, set for a couple hours.
That's it.
How many hush puppies you think
you make in a day?
-10,000.
-I'm sorry.
Hush puppies in a day.
Not how many times
do you blink.
10,000.
That's why you got
to have the machine.
Exactly.
And this is the process
in which you fill it?
Yes.
Fast, isn't it?
[ Laughter ]
They coming out as two
or three?
Three at a time.
And how do you know
when they're done?
They'll turn golden brown.
That is my size hush puppy,
right there.
It's a savory doughnut hole.
[ Laughs ]
That's why you're
the hush puppy king.
Needs a crown.
Da-da!
All right, time
to have the chowder?
Try the chowder.
Let's go.
There's only one thing
really wrong with this.
You haven't invented
the triple spooner.
Now, if you could just
get it like that,
in a rotating shovel
of spoons in my face...
[ Crew member laughs ]
Mmm.
The key, in my opinion,
is the right amount of clams
and the right amount of roux.
It's not too thick.
This is like "Welcome home"
clam chowder.
You sell this by
the gallon, too?
Try not to.
How about the refillable bowl?
Oh, yeah.
We have that.
Mnh-mnh.
You have to pay for it
each time, but we'll refill it.
[ Laughter ]
That's it!
That's it.
It's your show!
Good luck.
WAITRESS:
Clam chowder with hush puppies.
The clam chowder
is phenomenal.
I mean, it's got a lot
of clams in it.
You like real clam chowder,
that's what you're looking for.
the hush puppies here are great.
They're fried to perfection --
tender on the inside,
crunchy on the outside.
Whole flounder!
Something Fishy is
an extremely popular place.
FIERI: How'd you come up
with that name?
'Cause when I think
of something fishy,
it usually means somebody's
doing something bad.
Like, "That's a little fishy."
Yeah.
I said, "I think it needs
to be something fishy,"
meaning something
pertaining to fish,
and they said,
"That's a good name."
FIERI:
And it definitely describes
what's piled on the plates here.
Sampler up!
The sampler platter
has scallops,
clam strips, fried shrimp.
Any Southerner's buffet.
Luke,
I am your fish fryer.
So how many different items
are gonna be
on this sampler platter?
Seven different things
are gonna be on it.
We'll fillet a flounder.
So what's happening is,
the bones are going like this,
so he's riding them real tight
with that boning knife.
A good fish monger will be able
to get you
the best yield out of it
and not leave a lot
on the skeleton.
Next, what are we
gonna make?
Seafood breader.
Secret breader?
Seafood breader?
If it's secret breader,
we don't have to shoot it.
Eh, we can shoot it.
Okay.
Corn meal,
self-rising flour, salt.
Now we're gonna
dredge our seafood.
They go into the milk,
the breader,
and then they go
into the fryer.
-Okay.
-Cocktail sauce.
Ketchup, horseradish.
Lots of it.
Lemon juice,
Worcestershire sauce.
And this just gets
better with time.
So, when this gets to
set up for a day,
it's way better.
This is a real platter?
Or is this just, "Hey,
I'm gonna see if Guy Fieri
won't fit back in his Camaro?"
We'll try that.
Oysters, sea scallops, shrimp.
That's not a real amount
of shrimp.
Clam strips, piece of flounder,
and a deviled crab.
Coleslaw, steamed shrimp.
Holy moly!
The batter's nice and light.
Seafood shines through.
Not overly oily.
Cocktail sauce has got
a nice tang.
You've kept it old-school
and you've done it great.
It's delicious.
WAITRESS:
Sampler for you two.
Can you eat the whole
sampler platter?
-No.
-Okay, good.
'Cause I thought
I was the only one.
Scallop platter up!
So what we have here,
ladies and gentlemen,
is we have the mom and great
aunt of Matt "The Beaver."
You've seen all
the things Matt shot.
What do you think
of this little seafood joint?
I like this place.
They did it right?
They do it better than
any I have ever had.
You know I got this on tape?
Well, if Matt has -- Do you
have tape in the camera today?
Okay, good.
MAN: I love the atmosphere.
I love the fish.
It's always good.
You've got the right attitude,
the right energy,
and you do this
with such a real-deal,
straight-forward approach.
I enjoy it.
Good.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to FoodNetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
There's just one person
standing here in the
hush puppy department?
-That's it.
-What's it have on your résumé?
"Well, for the last 27 years,
I've worked
the hush puppy department."
[ Laughter ]