Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rollin' out,
looking for America's greatest
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
This trip...
[ Laughs ]
Mm-hmm-hmm.
...we're hittin'
up all-American joints...
Oh, yeah.
...all over the country...
Yee-haw!
...from scratch cooking
in California...
This is awesome.
...to East Coast Coney dogs...
I wanna eat where he cooks.
...elevated mountain grub
in the Rockies...
Flavor jets just turned on.
...and a spicy taste of Texas.
I dig that.
Plus, a hidden gem
in the Northwest...
It's real food.
That's real deal.
...burgers and barbecue...
Nice.
...Thanksgiving trimmings...
Top notch.
...and of course,
a trip down Route 66.
Interesting.
I've never seen this.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here
in Troutdale, Oregon,
about 18 miles from
downtown Portland
to check out a joint
here on Highway 30
right along the Sandy River
that opened in the 1940s
feeding loggers and locals.
Well, it turned into
all kinds of restaurants
until it ended up being
closed as a biker bar.
It's been reopened, refurbished,
and renewed by
a local restaurant owner
that I hear
is a real firecracker.
This is Shirley's Tippy Canoe.
Hey, Diner Guy, you wanna
race for some pink slips?
[ Tires screech ]
♪♪
If I would describe
Shirley in one phrase,
it would be high speed,
low drag.
[ Women laugh ]
-Quite the sassy little gal.
FIERI: A sass that 40-year
restaurant vet Shirley Welton
brought to the table when she
picked up this joint in '07.
You might say it was
a biker bar.
It used to get
pretty rough here.
Shirley has done
a wonderful job here.
♪♪
I think she's Superwoman.
No, no, no, just have a lot
of energy, that's all.
[ Laughs ]
This is starting to
get a little surreal.
♪♪
FIERI: But the food is keeping
everything grounded.
WOMAN: Captain's Plate.
Everything Shirley does
is homemade and fresh.
-Sloppy joe.
-Thank you.
FIERI: Just the way
her mama taught her.
♪♪
Well, we're gonna
make sloppy joes.
♪♪
I'm gonna go ahead
and gonna cut it in half.
Where did you learn to cook?
From my ma.
-You're amazing.
-[ Laughs ]
All right, we're gonna take
this and go grind it up?
Okay, let's do it.
[ Whirring ]
-We're gonna grind it twice.
-Okay, go ahead.
All right, so we take this
and we make sloppy joes.
Yes.
Gunpowder. [ Laughs ]
We're making gunpowder?
We're making gunpowder.
That's our spices.
All this goes to gunpowder?
Salt, paprika,
then we're gonna go ahead
and put some celery salt in it,
and we're gonna
put nutmeg, curry.
Curry.
Just a little.
Allspice, ground white pepper.
-Thyme?
-Thank you.
-Thyme after thyme, huh?
-Very, very nice then.
Ground bay leaves.
And marjoram.
Coriander.
And then we're gonna go --
Cayenne?
Yeah -- oh, cayenne,
here we are.
Whoa! Whoo!
Hey, we gotta put
some zip into it.
Granulated garlic.
Got some garlic.
A little clove.
Oh, yeah.
Whoo, whoo-hoo!
Lighting it up with the clove.
Trust me, honey.
Onion powder.
And there we go with
onion powder for 50 points.
-Sage.
-Cumin.
-And the last one?
-Ginger. [ Laughs ]
-Yeah.
I've never had more fun
mixing spices.
[ Laughs ]
Snap it down, okay? There.
[ Whirs ]
-All right.
-[ Whistles ]
Gunpowder.
Hyah!
[ Imitates gunshot, laughs ]
♪♪
Gonna make the sloppy joe.
Okay, let's brown
the meat here.
♪♪
Next up, white onions.
Green peppers, celery,
some cayenne, some salt.
We're gonna take some oregano,
chili powder and bay leaves,
and then we have
some minced garlic,
some black pepper,
and then we have some cumin.
-All that together.
-Yep, give it a swirl here.
Get after this.
Smells great so far.
-Okay.
Worcestershire sauce,
vinegar.
-Lemon-lime soda?
-Uh-huh.
[ Crickets chirp ]
Tomato sauce, tomato soup.
Now how long are we
gonna let this cook?
Oh, gonna simmer it
for probably an hour.
And what are we
gonna serve it with?
We're gonna serve it
with a hamburger patty.
Gunpowder.
[ Sizzling ]
♪♪
Put the sauce on.
Cheese, and then
we're gonna steam it.
♪♪
[ Whistles ]
Finish it off with
the green onion.
I notice that there's
no top for the bun.
It's underneath there.
We don't close ours.
Mmm, nice little
medium rare burger.
You get a lot of burger
in this,
and it's not just...
a bunch of sloppy joe.
But this is hearty.
♪♪
It's real food.
That's real deal.
♪♪
That's a good burger.
Sloppy burger joe.
Sloppy joe burger.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Not like a normal sloppy joe.
Spice on it that just kinda
lingers in your mouth.
It's a little bit of sweet,
too, so it's perfect for me.
I love coming here.
FIERI: And getting here, well,
that's half the adventure.
MAN: It's a very fun drive.
You sit out here in the
beautiful Douglas fir trees
that are native to
the Pacific Northwest.
♪♪
Hamburger steak.
It doesn't matter what you have,
it's always good.
Chicken-fried steak.
SHIRLEY:
Table eight, Polish dip.
The Polish sausage
French dip is very good.
Pork butt, there you go.
Pork butt, there we are.
And this we're cutting up
to make the Polish sausage.
Mm-hmm.
My mom came from the old school.
You did it all, you know.
You cut and grind it yourself,
a kind of a coarse
grind in there.
Yes, it is.
Put half of
the ingredients in,
then I put the seasoning in.
-Garlic.
-The garlic.
A little sage.
Pepper, salt, marjoram.
And then we put the rest in.
So it's right in the middle.
All right, here we go.
[ Whirring ]
'Cause we don't have all day.
[ Shaky voice ]
I can't hold onto it any longer.
-Well, let's just stop it.
-Okay.
♪♪
Make the patty.
About seven ounces.
And it has to be
kind of elongated.
So we're gonna put
the sausage down.
[ Sizzles ]
Put a little butter here,
put the onions,
and then we put
the green pepper,
the brown sugar,
and put it on the...
On the onions?
On the onions
to caramelize the onions.
So we cook both sides.
So the au jus is ready?
The au jus is ready.
Nice little toast on that.
Here we are.
[ Whistles ]
Nice patty.
Going Paul Bunyan or what?
♪♪
And then we stab it.
A sausage sandwich
usually is juicy enough.
Why put a dip with it?
Well, you try it
and see what you think.
♪♪
Good sausage sandwich,
you know.
Mm-hmm.
Peppers and onions,
you can't beat that.
But now dip it.
All right.
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
That makes it.
I mean, it's good as it is --
not overseasoned,
the nice toasted bread,
then that bread soaks up
some of the au jus.
♪♪
When you stop by here,
that's kind of the old-school
sandwich you'd wanna have.
♪♪
It's the best food around.
Just a wonderful,
wonderful place.
FIERI:
Just all the components --
sitting in the nostalgic room.
I mean, just has a really
cool feel about it.
Make sure she's here
when you come down.
♪♪
Coming up, what's more
Americana than Route 66?
Doing this right.
So we're hitting up
one of the historic stops...
I just...
...for some legendary
chicken and fixings.
It's like
the Colorado Cheese River
running right through
Flavortown.
♪♪
It was back in the '40s
this place started
frying up chicken
for drivers on the old Route 66
here in Willowbrook, Illinois.
Well, then the new highway
was built,
and a lot of folks took it.
That didn't close this place.
Dell Rhea's Chicken Basket
is in the Illinois
Route 66 Hall of Fame --
and for good reason.
-It's the chicken.
-Two chicken dinners.
They're famous for the chicken,
and I love it.
-This is my second helping.
-Chicken basket up.
This is so good.
It's been around
for years and years.
This fried chicken recipe
has been going on here
since the '30s?
Mid to late '30s. We're not sure
of the exact date.
[ Whistles ]
That's some chicken history.
Yes, it is.
FIERI: Handed down to
owner Patrick Rhea...
Six up, please.
...from his dad Dell,
who bought the place in '63.
I was 9 years old.
So you were in here
at 9 years old...
Busing tables,
washing glasses.
FIERI: And learning how to
keep folks coming back.
That's two chicken baskets up.
It's one of the reasons that
I do everything like I do.
I do it from scratch,
I do it homemade.
FIERI:
And he's doing it by the ton.
Get those two chickens out.
FIERI: Seriously,
2,000 pounds a week.
Walk me through the principles.
We're gonna brine this.
Take some salt.
Gives the meat the flavor.
-And some sugar?
-No sugar.
That's interesting.
Now how long's it gonna
stay in salt?
This is gonna stay
in salt for 24 hours
before we do anything to it.
Makes a profound difference,
you say.
Absolutely.
And then we're gonna what?
Bread it with flour, milk,
and a special
bread crumb we use.
Comes only from a Chicago
bakery, extra-fine grain.
Now do you let this set up
on this breading here
for a while, or...
Yeah, this has gotta sit for
between four and six hours.
Once those juices kinda
work into those bread crumbs
and it kinda all sticks
together, then we'll fry it.
What, about 350, 325?
Nah, that's part
of our secret.
We cook at a very
different temperature.
We're at 260,
cook for 20 minutes.
-No.
-Yep.
Now this is not
what you would call
a Southern hard fried chicken.
Interesting.
I've never seen this.
44 years I've been here,
every time I eat this chicken,
it amazes me.
We're good to go.
Do you let it sit there
and drain a little bit?
Let it sit and drain.
Let it cool down.
Let the juices
coagulate a little bit.
Gotta let your juices
coagulate.
You got to do that.
There she is.
Look how tender that is.
It's just juicy,
falls right off the bone.
Hmm, really nice
crunchy coating.
When you bite into it,
you're getting good
breading and good bird.
You really pick up that salt.
It's got some nice flavor
to it.
Breading,
as simple as it is,
coats well with the chicken
and makes it nice and --
nice and crunchy.
You could tell I didn't like it.
-Good chicken.
-Thank you.
-The chicken is so moist.
-I love the breading.
WOMAN: The breading is key.
It's very light and fresh.
-Great flavor.
-Super tiny flaky fall apart-y.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: The way it's been
for decades.
Every time we come here,
exactly the same.
Throwback from like
the '50s or '60s.
Something my parents
would've come to.
Now I can experience the same
thing that they experienced.
Thank you.
FIERI: From the original
fried chicken
to everything that's been
added over the years,
like roasted chicken
and chicken pot pie.
And the soup.
FIERI: That'd be
chicken dumpling, and get this.
My husband like the gizzards,
but I've never tasted one.
FIERI: Patrick's even
doing his own take
on this bar food classic.
12 piece buffalo wing up.
♪♪
Mmm.
That's good.
I mean, it really is.
Look at that.
Nice and juicy.
Mmm. Blue cheese is nice
and creamy and tangy.
You know, what I really
like about that
is it holds on to
some of the herbs
and some of the spices.
Look at how juicy it is.
Good meat, not too spicy.
You know what?
That's a good wing.
FIERI: And they're doing this
comfort food classic...
Do you have a mac and cheese?
FIERI: ...one order at a time.
Macaroni and cheese --
all basic, old school.
Butter and flour.
Okay.
I make a little
old-fashioned roux.
Equal parts.
Equal parts, one to one,
and sauté some onions.
Guy, would you hand me
that wine over there?
I was just drinking that.
-Now you made this recipe up?
-Yes, I did.
I took some old classics,
tuned them up just a little bit,
made them the way I wanted.
While that's cooking,
I'm gonna start adding
some seasonings to this.
All right.
Salt, white pepper, thyme.
Thyme.
We're gonna make a savory
sauce out of it anyway,
so I think that thyme goes
well with the cheese.
Okay, gonna take our onion,
wine, and butter.
Okay.
Add the roux,
cook it all together.
So we've got our
bechamel just about
to the consistency we want it.
Tightens up nice.
Nice and tight.
Now we're gonna add
a bunch of seasonings.
Dry mustard, salt,
white pepper.
Paprika for a little color.
Paprika.
Now what kind of cheese
are we gonna add?
We use three kinds.
I'm gonna use parmesan,
I'm gonna use asiago,
and I'm gonna use sharp cheddar.
Do you add it all
in one time,
or you go little by little?
I pretty much add 'em
one at at time.
Get this melted in there and
we'll add the other two cheeses.
If you want to dump that
asiago in, that'd be great.
Parmesan.
I like that,
so you get a little bit
of the sweet and sharp
from the asiago and the parm
and the creaminess
from the cheddar.
Okay, cheese sauce is done.
We'll take that with the pasta,
put it in the dish
and bake it.
Shouldn't we taste that?
Mmm. Well, that's
creamy goodness.
It's like
the Colorado Cheese River
running right
through Flavortown.
Macaroni.
So every time
somebody orders this,
you cook the pasta to order?
Yes, sir.
That's what you do
in Italian restaurants.
You cook your pasta fresh.
No, I'm down with it.
Cool.
I'm picking up what you're
laying down, brother.
Yeah, and then some more on
would be good.
A little bit more cheese.
In the oven she goes.
About 10 minutes of
knick-knack paddy-whack?
It's about 20, actually.
I like to give it -- yeah.
Really?
Oh, so you really like
to let it caramelize up.
I like nice and brown
on the top.
Look at that.
There's not many places
you can find anymore
where you get custom-made
mac and cheese.
Mm, that's creamy.
Good.
That's mac and cheese
right there.
That sharp cheddar --
really nice, velvety.
Mmm. Doing this right.
Thank you.
You're Captain Creamy now.
[ Laughs ]
That cheese was excellent,
just right.
It's comfort food.
Good eating experience
all the way around.
The food is delicious.
This is satisfying my hunger.
That's what I like to hear.
My son Hunter or Ryder
would go bananas for this.
You know what bananas are?
Kinda like oranges?
Bananas are good.
Silly Captain Creamy.
Up next,
we're headed to Houston...
-Oh, gosh!
-...for some Texas hash...
You gotta try this.
...and a burger
that eats like an inferno.
My mouth is, like, literally
on fire at this point.
♪♪
I'm here in the Midtown
neighborhood
of Houston, Texas --
now it's also been known
as Montrose
or the old Fourth Ward --
to visit a funky little joint
that opened as a grocery store
back in '39.
Now in the early '70s, they
started serving sandwiches,
and in '77 they
introduced the burger.
The rest is history.
This is Lankford Grocery.
The best hamburger you will
ever eat in your entire life.
Whew!
It's made the old-fashioned way.
Tell me what you need, boys.
FIERI: By owner and local legend
Eydie Lankford Prior.
Lotta burgers.
FIERI: She grew up here.
The front part was
a grocery store,
this was our kitchen,
and we lived upstairs.
Hi, guys.
FIERI: And it was Eydie's dad
who started serving
the burgers back in '77.
The burgers took over,
and then it just started
getting bigger and bigger.
-Okay, y'all enjoy.
-It's all made to order.
-FIERI: 10 different ways.
-Okay, you guys.
From the
South of the Border Burger...
Avocados, the pico de gallo --
it's always spectacular.
FIERI: ...to the double bacon
cheddar burger...
It's a giant burger, it's great.
FIERI: ...to the house special.
Our house burger.
It will set your mouth on fire.
FIERI: Because it's loaded with
a three-pepper hot sauce.
Looks like mustard,
but it's not.
I'm actually nervous
at this point.
Okay, we're gonna make some
firehouse sauce for you.
Vinegar, add serranos,
jalapeños, habaneros.
Okay. Did I see habanero
plants in the back?
You saw habaneros in the back.
We grow our own
because we wanna make sure
they're good and hot.
Go back there and pick out
the prime ones.
Pick out the ones we want
and throw it in
that little old pot.
They just cook
till they're soft.
-These are done.
-Mmm.
Mm-hmm.
No gloves or anything
with that, Eydie.
Absolutely not.
We're just kind of
blending these things up.
There is no way
that that is not gonna
be a million degrees.
Along with that goes
garlic, onions, radishes.
You're just gonna love it.
That is going to kill my mouth.
There we go.
Then we're going to
pour this in here,
add some mustard.
Mustard.
Whose recipe is this?
We really don't know
where this came from.
Someone said,
"I want something spicy."
I want something --
Eydie came back here
and went "Ha ha ha."
Mm-hmm-hmm.
And that is it.
Part of me right now
is dying to just
take a taste of it,
and the other part
of me is just praying
that the bun and the burger
and all the apparatus
will cool it down enough.
Will cool it down.
So now we're gonna put
this on the burger?
Yes, we are.
We're cooking the burger
for the firehouse.
So this burger's gonna
go salt and pepper.
What else goes on this burger?
We have our cayenne butter.
We're gonna melt
a little butter.
Uh-huh.
Cayenne pepper,
and let's see, okeydoke.
Quit looking at me and add more.
Ooh!
I just wanna see if you're
gonna be able to handle this.
Okay.
That butter's gonna go
right on top of this patty.
Ooh, maybe a little bit more.
-Some American cheese.
-Wonderful mustard sauce.
A little bit more,
a little bit more.
Jalapeños, lettuce.
See how quick she covered
it up with the lettuce?
Not there.
I did.
I don't want you to see it.
Onions, tomatoes,
pickles, and there it is.
This is kinda like licking
the volcano in Flavortown.
♪♪
Mmm!
Oh, that is hot.
That is really good.
Oh, gosh!
Nice hot,
and you still get flavor.
My mouth is, like, literally
on fire at this point.
If I just keep eating, it'll
cool it for, like, 20 seconds.
Oh, my tongue's
completely numb now.
I almost bit it off.
I bet you that's flammable.
You could take that sauce
and put that on raw chicken.
It would cook it.
[ Laughs ]
You know what? I dig that.
The spices that they use --
amazing.
I'm starting to tear up.
They're burger tears.
Happy tears.
They're definitely not
your cookie cutter burger.
Can't get it anywhere else.
Two double meat cheeseburgers.
Handmade like your
grandmother used to make.
FIERI: The way they've been
making 'em here since '77.
Yeah, we'd maybe cook 10 a day,
then we had to do 12,
then we had to do 14.
FIERI: Now they're crankin' out
more than 200 a day.
You guys enjoy.
They'll cook anything
that you want.
Especially for the regulars,
they customize it.
Okay, here we go, Jordan.
FIERI: She'll even
name one after you...
-Grim burger.
-This is the elusive Mr. Grim.
FIERI: ...with Eydie's homemade
mac and cheese.
Why not put it on the
burger with jalapeños,
bacon, and egg? They all
fit together pretty nice.
We either come here for the
burger or for the special.
-We always get the special.
-That looks terrific.
'Cause on Wednesdays
you get enchiladas.
Thursdays is
chicken-fried steak day.
Wait a second, you know
the specials by heart?
Oh, yeah.
-What's our special today?
-Texas hash.
Texas chicken hash,
it's fantastic.
When you come to Texas
and you get hash,
you gonna get it with chicken?
Well, only here.
Okay.
This is my thing.
"This is my thing!" Word.
[ Laughs ]
Season it.
Chili powder, garlic,
just a handful, no measurement.
A little bit of black pepper.
We're gonna bake this,
don't ask me how long,
just till I can
smell it cooked done.
You're a smell cooker.
When I can smell it,
then I know it's done.
So no oil or anything,
just pop it in there,
No oil.
You got the chicken fat.
Now what's gonna happen, we'll
bring that out, chop it up?
Gonna dice this up nice,
little bit of butter.
The whole farm
on that one there.
Yeah, potatoes.
We're gonna brown 'em up,
kinda a little crispy.
We're gonna add a little
bell pepper to it.
Gonna add some onions,
black pepper.
Then we're gonna
add this chicken.
Gonna stir that in,
little seasoning.
-Just let that crisp up.
-Hash is good.
We're going to get us
some of these tortillas,
fried real crisp, put
this mixture on top of it.
When you said hash,
I didn't expect that.
With a little queso on the top.
What's in the queso?
Milk, bell peppers, jalapeños,
maybe one or two habaneros.
Slurry of flour and milk.
-A little roux.
-Thicken it up a little bit.
And the cheese.
It's American cheese.
And that's it. And we just kind
of drizzle that over the top,
and it's a little spicy.
-No, here?
-Nah.
-Eydie, spicy? No.
-Spicy, no.
Tomatoes and avocados.
-Crunch up that tortilla there.
-Ooh.
That's the way
I like it right there.
Mmm. Aw, it's great.
That's some
righteous hash, girl.
Well, you know what
the kicker is here?
-The tortillas.
-Is the -- absolutely.
But the extra kicker,
that cheese sauce.
It's almost like
a Mexican alfredo.
You gotta try this.
Nice job.
Thank you, sir.
-That is really good.
-Good.
It's always kinda never hit or
miss 'cause it's always a hit.
-Okay, the Migas?
-You name it,
everything tastes great.
Plenty of habanero.
They do a fabulous job.
It's made with loving hands,
just like Mom.
It's just a good
old hole in the wall,
everybody's nice,
the food is great.
Enjoy.
This is definitely our
favorite burger place.
You, my friend --
I will tell you something --
[ Laughs ]
have done an outstanding job.
-You got a lot to be proud of.
-Thank you, sir.
-Great job.
-[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up
on this all-American hour...
Okay, so it's old school.
...a scratch-cookin'
cafe in Carmel...
We're gonna have to go to the
gym after this, aren't we?
...going full tilt when it comes
to their biscuits.
You have license to
use extreme, man.
♪♪
I'm just like you.
I like to go on road trips
with my buddies,
check out funky joints,
eat great food.
So here I am
in Carmel, California,
to check out a joint
where I hear they're
scratch-baking everything,
and the biscuits are the bomb.
This is From Scratch.
Okay, Robert, no more driving.
Time to come in and eat.
Let's go.
Aw, Dad, I thought you
said I could drive.
♪♪
Cinnamon French toast
in the window.
California dip
on our homemade roll.
-Homey, delicious meals.
-They put a little love in it.
FIERI: And that love comes
from the family tree,
because when Stephen Grebing
and his wife Carolyn
bought the joint in '95,
he most certainly
tapped into his roots.
Where did you learn how to cook?
My mother and my grandmother.
-Okay, so it's old school then.
-Old school.
FIERI: Yeah, old school
in hyperdrive.
Extreme double sausage
biscuits and gravy.
You have the little
sausage gravy,
but then you have a sausage
patty under the sausage gravy,
and then cheese biscuits
under that.
FIERI: Good thing I got
my health nut compadre
Chef Robert Irvine
along for the ride.
I've already been in
the gym two hours.
Oh!
And I'm eating
breakfast at 8:00.
I want you to count
just how many times we
will talk about the gym,
how many times
we'll see flexing.
Don't hate this.
It's hard work.
[ British accent ]
It's a machine.
Right, isn't it?
I put a lot of time in it.
Have you had
a biscuit and gravy?
I have, many times. So tell me
about the biscuits then.
So we're gonna start
with the flour.
We put in powdered milk.
Then we're gonna add some
sugar and baking soda.
Okay.
-Salt.
-Okay.
Cream of tartar.
Now we add the cream cheese.
This is awesome.
Now is it cold cream cheese
like we're doing cold butter?
Yes. Yes.
Okay.
Little bit of butter.
Incorporates it in.
♪♪
And we're gonna
make up our wet mix.
Okay.
And to that we add buttermilk.
A little bit more
melted butter, baking soda.
Okay, now we mix it up?
Yep.
And then we're gonna add
the cheddar cheese.
♪♪
And we'll roll it to
about 3/4 inch thick.
So then we'll cut 'em.
♪♪
In the oven, 350, how long?
For about 35, 40 minutes.
Now we're gonna
make our sausage.
We start with
fresh ground pork.
-Just pork, nothing else?
-Just pork, yeah.
-Okay.
-So to that we're gonna add
thyme, marjoram, sage, ginger.
That's different.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion,
salt, maple sugar,
sambal chili paste.
And mix it, mix it,
mix it.
Okay, are we gonna give this
a chance to kind of marry,
kind of bring
some flavor together?
We're gonna let this go
for overnight.
Excellent.
Now we're gonna cook
our house-made sausage.
I'm so hungry.
This better be good.
[ British accent ]
All Robert had this morning
was two sips of air
and a brief whiff of coffee.
And it was a whiff.
♪♪
It's got a great smell.
Now we're gonna start
the gravy,
and we'll add yellow onions,
salt, white pepper.
[ Normal voice ] Some A.P.?
We're gonna build some roux?
Yep.
Are we going full,
heavy cream, half-and-half?
We're going
half-and-half.
And we'll let this simmer,
just tighten up for how long?
About 15, 20 minutes.
Bring out the biscuits,
put it together.
Yes.
Nice biscuit.
There you go.
Give it a nice,
little toast.
We're gonna make two patties
and cook this on the flattop.
We toasted the biscuit up.
Sausage here.
Now we put our sausage
and gravy on there.
♪♪
Fresh green parsley.
You want to try some?
Here you go.
[ Utensil clinks ]
Oh, what happened
to yours, Robert?
Look at that. It's like
a fight to get in there.
The cheddar in the biscuit
is bananas.
Then on top of it,
the sausage patty.
But you know what?
It's that sambal
in that sausage patty
that just gives it
a little bit of that extra heat.
Yep.
The gravy's creamy.
And it's
not dry and gritty.
It's thick and pretty.
You have license
to use "extreme," man.
That's pretty out-of-bounds.
Thank you.
Oh, I got to tell you --
it's amazing.
I don't eat fat,
and this is really good.
I mean, it's really good.
Thank you.
Nice job. Excellent job, Chef.
Thank you, thank you.
♪♪
Extreme biscuits and gravy up.
They're fantastic.
These biscuits and gravy
are crazy-good.
I've been to
800 locations.
How many joints you guys been to
on "Triple D"?
262. And today would be...
That's not a gut
that says "262."
And this is 263 today?
Today. Absolutely.
The menu is so good.
Definitely lots of
comfort food.
FIERI:
Like this hearty bowl that'll
make you want to power nap.
All right, Chef,
what are we making?
We're gonna make From Scratch
brisket chili.
The meat is tender
and the right blend of spicy.
If I could make chili, I wish
I could make it like this.
It's amazing.
♪♪
We start
with a full brisket.
Doctor. Doctor.
And we're gonna cube it
and go with the one-inch cube.
Dig it.
From Scratch house seasoning
that we make.
When we cook,
we layer flavors, right?
This is important --
to season every step of the way.
All right, let's go.
We're gonna sear it
on the flattop.
Okay.
Okay, so, now you got it
browned all the way around.
Now we'll hit it
with a little onion.
Caramelize those a bit.
Yep.
Now where are we at?
Well, we're gonna build
our chili.
Hit it.
We'll start off with our
fresh-made chicken stock.
We got the beef stock.
Chili powder
that we blended.
That you made yourself.
Chicken base, beef base,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion.
Fresh, toasted cumin.
Cocoa powder.
You got to have a little
chocolate in the bottom of
that. I'll give it to you.
Chopped garlic.
Seared-off brisket
with the onions.
Crushed tomatoes.
Tomato paste.
A little raisin paste.
Okay.
And then
we'll add one beer.
We'll let that cook down
a little bit.
How long?
For an hour.
Plate up our chili.
Okay.
I'm gonna use
red kidney beans.
From dry. I love that.
♪♪
Incredible.
It's rich. It's flavorful.
The meat's tender,
but you find the meat.
There's definitely --
Right, and that's
why you cube it large.
You taste the little sweetness
of the raisin in there,
just counterbalance
that heat.
I get a couple levels
of sweetness.
That's a phenomenal chili.
Thank you.
Just the right amount
of heat.
♪♪
We're gonna have to go to
the gym after this, aren't we?
Yep.
Brisket chili.
MAN: I like it because it's got
big chunks of meat in it.
They don't play around.
WOMAN: It's not too hot,
but it's spicy.
It's the best chili I've had.
Chef, had a great time.
Thank you.
Thank you, Guy.
Mr. Irvine.
And send me some of
the biscuits and gravy.
Peace.
♪♪
Up next, a rustic spot
in Wilson, Wyoming...
Look at that.
Get after it.
...serving up a whole lot
of comfort...
A little
labor of love here.
...with a culinary spin.
That's gourmet French toast.
♪♪
So, I'm here in the great state
of Wyoming,
right on Highway 22,
about 6 or 7 miles west
of Jackson Hole.
I mean, everybody knows
about Jackson Hole, right?
So I'm here to check out this
family-run neighborhood joint
where they are
scratch-making everything
for breakfast, lunch,
and dinner.
This is Nora's Fish Creek Inn.
♪♪
Prime rib, baked potato!
A unique little log cabin.
There's a giant fish on the top.
It's a normal Joe place
that you feel comfortable,
and there's great food.
Blue cheese mushrooms, please!
♪♪
I've been coming here
for 30-plus years,
watching Kat grow up here.
FIERI: Working for her mother,
Nora Tygum,
who started the joint
back in '82.
Now Kat's picking up
where her mother left off.
I've modified a lot
of her recipes,
but a lot of them I keep
the same because it's Nora's.
The food here is excellent.
Any meal here, any day.
It's one of our favorite places
to have breakfast.
Biscuit and gravy
and the huevos rancheros.
The pancakes, the French toast.
Banana bread French toast!
It's fantastic.
Banana bread sourdough
whole-wheat French toast.
...whole-wheat French toast.
Wow!
Let's do this.
Brown sugar, white sugar,
and a pound of butter.
Cream this.
Look at that.
Get after it.
Now I'm gonna add the eggs,
a couple at a time, mix again.
♪♪
Now I'll add my sourdough.
Flavor jets just turned on.
White flour,
whole-wheat flour,
salt, soda,
nutmeg, cinnamon.
-Cinnamon.
-Allspice.
-Clove?
-A little clove.
And some baking powder.
Correct.
Now we're going to add
the dry ingredients
to the wet ingredients,
and I'll mix this.
♪♪
Then I mash up the bananas,
and then
I'll scoop them in.
And then you're going to put
the mixer back to --
Back to work.
[ Whirring ]
A little
labor of love here.
I like to let it sit
for about 30 minutes.
Hit it
with a little Aqua Net.
Then I'm gonna pour it
in the pan.
325 for an hour?
Yep.
♪♪
All right,
so, bread's cooled down now.
♪♪
It's three slices,
50/50 margarine and butter,
dip it in my eggs.
Did we put any milk
in the egg?
Nope, just egg.
Put it on the flattop.
Look at that omelette you have
on the outside of that.
Plate this up.
♪♪
Powdered sugar, walnuts,
and some blueberries.
Breakfast avalanche you got
going on over here.
♪♪
That's gourmet
French toast.
The whole wheat,
the bananas,
I mean, the whole spice cabinet
jumped in this one.
I love the allspice
getting in there.
There's enough sweetness
in there,
and the natural sweetness
of the blueberries coming in.
That's lights out.
Nicely done.
Awesome.
Ooh, you know the knuckles.
I do.
I like this one.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
The banana bread
is just unbelievable.
I love it so much that I just
want to keep eating it.
You look out your window,
and you see the Teton Mountains
all around you.
You can't take it for granted
because it's just so beautiful.
We come here a lot during
the week, during lunches.
Dinner, I have stroganoff
or prime rib.
FIERI: Or why not have both
at the same time?
Pick up, stroganoff!
You make your beef stroganoff
with prime rib?
Leftover prime rib.
So you'll serve this
for dinner.
You have your end trimmings,
your leftover prime rib,
then you'll take that,
slice that up,
and use that to make
the stroganoff.
Correct.
Got it.
♪♪
All right,
let's get into it.
We're making the homemade
noodles for the beef stroganoff.
So, all-purpose flour.
A little salt, milk,
my eggs.
And some clarified butter.
Got it.
Mix it up with my hands,
and I'm gonna knead it
to a nice ball.
And then I'm gonna
flour my surface
so they don't
stick together.
Roll it out, cut it in half,
and roll it up.
Slice it.
Big, hearty noodles.
♪♪
Unroll 'em,
kind of break 'em apart,
let 'em dry out a little bit
on this cookie sheet.
Okay,
so we bust all this out.
Okay, so now we're gonna make
the stroganoff.
Yes.
So, we got
the clarified butter.
Melting with my garlic,
mushrooms, onions.
Let this sauté up
a little bit.
I'll add my flour,
building a little roux.
Then I'm gonna add
the leftover prime rib,
half and half, tarragon,
cracked black pepper,
chicken stock, wine.
So, in the winter months,
when everybody's
freezing cold up here,
this has got to be a hit.
Yes.
What temperatures on
a daily basis in December?
Minus 28.
Your hair freezes.
That's what happened.
[ Laughter ]
Let that come to a boil.
I'm gonna drop my noodles.
Noodles have puffed up.
♪♪
Here's what I dig.
Super creamy.
I love the tarragon
in there.
You get a ton of meat.
You get a nice, big, fat,
hand-rolled noodle.
So it used to be
just on Wednesdays, huh?
Yep.
I guess I'll have to put it
on the menu.
That's me working
for you guys.
Nice job, girl.
Excellent. Delicious.
WOMAN:
The beef stroganoff.
The best thing about it is the
mushroom sauce that's cooked in.
I really enjoy
the homemade noodles.
I mean, you don't get them
very often.
So, this is still
a locals joint?
-Very much local.
-WOMAN: Yeah.
-You might change that.
-It's not me.
You're the ones that said,
"Come here."
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up,
a barbecue joint
in Virginia Beach...
Good looking rub.
...stacking holiday dinners
all in one bite.
You're welcome to Thanksgiving
at my house anytime.
Then, a classic joint dishing
out classic dogs in Baltimore...
I like the flavor
already.
...Coney style for generations.
It's a legend.
♪♪
I'm here in Virginia Beach,
Virginia,
about 10 miles south
of the Chesapeake Bay
and about 10 miles
west of the Atlantic Ocean.
Now I've been through here
before and had everything
from seafood to homemade
ice cream cones.
But when I hear there's a dude
that's knocking out burnt ends,
North Carolina pulled pork,
and smoked turkey,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Whitner's Barbecue.
Pulled pork platter with
baked beans and green beans.
I love it.
Southern style barbecue.
FIERI: And then some.
The brisket is awesome.
-It reminds me of Texas.
-The St. Louis cut ribs --
my favorite meal here.
-This is the real deal.
FIERI: 'Cause owner
Warren Rogers...
Burnt end sandwich.
...started young.
Raised doing barbecue.
But it was only a hobby
till two years ago...
All right.
...when Warren
and his brother-in-law
Chris Janowski decided
to take the plunge...
It was sink or swim.
It was a career change for me.
Drop the 401K.
You got it.
...and started
cranking out the 'cue.
Brisket platter.
What makes good barbecue?
It's got to be the meat,
number one, being fresh.
And then, of course,
it's the seasoning.
FIERI: That'd be the house rub
that's going on this
Kansas City classic.
-Burnt end sandwich.
-Outstanding.
What are we making?
All right,
Mr. Whitner's barbecue rub.
Okay.
Paprika.
Hang on a second.
There you go.
Chili powder,
brown sugar, pepper,
ground celery.
Good-looking rub.
Salt, ground mustard.
[ Whistles ]
Cayenne.
And a little
granulated garlic.
Then it's all mixed up,
that's good to go.
There you go.
Okay, now we're making the beef.
You got it.
All right, so we're gonna start
with some barbecue rub.
Lot of salt.
And then we go with
the brown sugar
and some black pepper.
Look at that.
That is beautiful.
And that's it?
You got it.
And hit this all over
the brisket?
What I like to do is make sure
it gets a good coat
all the way around
and let that seasoning
work its way down.
All right, we're gonna grab
a couple more
and put them in the smoker.
At what temp?
200.
For how many hours?
This should be interesting.
12.
12?
12. Yep.
Nice.
Okay, what sauce are making?
Sweet sauce.
So get me started.
A little white vinegar.
That'll clear you out.
Cider vinegar.
Okay, a little chili powder?
Pepper.
You're too tall to be
doing that job.
That's all right.
Ground mustard.
Granulated garlic.
Some onion powder.
Whitner's barbecue rub.
Ground celery. Salt.
Mess of salt.
And brown sugar.
Man! Thank goodness you got
yourself a big old kettle.
You got it.
So we got this all mixed in.
What's next?
The pineapple juice.
And more pineapple juice.
Yeah.
Nice natural sweetener.
More cider vinegar?
Yep. Got to get that tang.
Wu-Tang.
There you go.
Big Wu-Tang Clan fan
over here.
[ Laughs ]
Some Worcestershire.
[ Whistles ]
A gallon of mustard.
You got it.
Hot sauce.
Tomato paste.
Bunch of goodness right there.
That's Lake Barbecue Sauce
over in Flavortown.
Yep. We got some
chipotle sauce.
And then we get some water
in there.
Okay. So how long you gonna
let this simmer?
Till everything
gets dissolved.
Then when it's done,
you just crank it,
pours it right out
to the bucket.
You got it.
Awesome. Okay.
-Now's the good part.
-[ Whistles ] Check this out.
You're gonna take
all the fat off it.
Yeah, on the burnt ends,
you really don't want
that extra fat in there.
Slice it into cubes.
You got it.
Hit it with sauce.
Yes.
That sauce is righteous.
All right, let's put this baby
under some foil.
We throw it back in the oven.
Oven at 350?
You got it. A good 45 minutes.
Okay.
Let's go in the oven and get
those burnt ends.
Just peel this baby back.
All right.
Just cooked it down and then
just absorbed the sauce.
Look at that big smoke ring
on that.
And that's how she goes.
♪♪
Mmm.
Good beef, nice rub,
good smoke.
-It's very rich.
-Mmm.
Sauce got a little sweet,
little heat, lot of vinegar.
Then you got a little bit of
that Worcestershire in the back.
Nice job. Really nice job.
Thank you. Appreciate it.
Hey, look, what's that
over there?
Got a burnt end sandwich
coming up.
It's just delicious.
The sauce complements the meat.
Tender, good flavor,
very good.
There it is.
Five dish platter.
It's comfort food.
FIERI: With homemade sides,
like potato salad
and dirty rice...
Sort of like my mother
cooking it.
FIERI: ...right down
to a holiday dinner every day.
Mr. Whitner's Smoked Turkey.
Like a Thanksgiving meal
in a bun.
FIERI: With cranberry chutney
and cornbread croutons.
It's delicious.
-Turkey time.
-You got it.
This is the turkey breast
for the Mr. Whitner's
Smoked Turkey.
Okay.
And we start off canola oil.
Then just put a little bit
of salt on there.
Rub that in.
And some of the barbecue rub
we made?
Yes. Rub our turkey breast.
Now we got to the smoker --
does it stay on the tray
or does it go on a rack?
We leave this on the tray.
Ready to roll?
Yep, off to the smoker.
All right.
And what do we smoke it with?
Hickory wood.
Okay.
All right, got some turkey.
Look at that.
How long was that down?
A couple hours.
We're gonna slice this turkey.
Mmm.
You're welcome to Thanksgiving
at my house anytime.
There you go.
That's the chutney
with cranberries there.
Yep. This is a spicy mayo.
Basically it's a curry,
some habanero mash.
-Okay.
-The cornbread crouton.
You crumble up a cornbread
crouton on here?
Yep. Nice little crunch.
Then we'll go ahead and put
a little lettuce on top there.
There you go.
Get a looky-loo at that.
♪♪
That right there --
that is a righteous
turkey sandwich, man.
Top notch.
♪♪
A lot of turkey.
Smoked perfectly.
The cranberry sauce
is right there for the tang.
But you want to know what
the crazy part is?
Was this little cornbread
crunchy-crunch
that he put in there.
It's like putting potato chips
on a sandwich when you're a kid.
I'll take 3,000 of them
to go, please.
-Nice job.
-Thank you.
Mr. Whitner's Smoked Turkey.
-It is fabulous.
-The turkey is fresh.
Got a nice smoked flavor to it.
41.
Here's your burnt ends sandwich.
This restaurant
does everything well.
But I will tell you, Warren,
you're rockin' it out, man.
Thanks for having me, man.
Appreciate it. Thank you.
FIERI: Now we're going
from turkey and 'cue
to another joint screaming
all-American.
In 1927, a Greek immigrant
by the name
of Gregory Diacumacos
opened a hot dog stand
in Baltimore
serving Coney Island-style dogs
with his own chili sauce recipe.
Now, it was a hit.
I mean, a big hit.
And 81 years later,
it still is.
WOMAN: I need two up on one,
five up on three,
two hold the onion.
Mmm!
There's something about
a G & A hot dog.
-Enjoy, enjoy.
-It makes me feel at home.
-Is that yummy?
-It tastes just scrumptious.
-It's a little bit of heaven.
-This is like an institution.
My grandfather's been coming
here since he was a kid,
my father.
No!
And take these.
FIERI: And it all began with
owner Andy Farantos'
great-uncle Gregory,
who partnered up
with his cousin Alex
and started a tradition.
He had it from 1927
to 1966,
and my father took it over
in '66 to '88 with my uncle.
FIERI: And then it was
Andy's turn.
Pick it up.
We kept all the old recipes.
We kept everything the same.
FIERI: And kept the crowds
packing in.
Best hot dog in town.
When I was a little kid,
we used to come up here
and get hot dogs and watch them
turning in the window.
FARANTOS:
You're gonna enjoy this one.
FIERI: Loaded with
the original Coney sauce.
Mmm! Delicious.
Andy has still not told me
what the secret ingredients are.
FIERI: On the dogs and the
burgers, even an omelet.
-It's the Coney sauce, isn't it?
-Yes, yeah.
-That's what does it.
-Absolutely.
Now it's time to make
the Coney Island sauce.
Yes. Every day we get
fresh ground beef delivered.
Do a lot of ground beef
around here.
Yeah, we sure do.
A little bit of water.
Oh, you're gonna get in there.
Yeah, you got to get in.
You got to get in.
You got to break down
the ground beef.
How many days a week
do you work?
Six days a week.
How many hours a day?
16 hours a day.
16 hours a day,
six days a week?
Yeah.
All right,
a little more water.
And then, Guy,
I need the paprika.
There we go. The celery salt
and the chili powder.
I'm gonna attach the milk crates
to your boots
and make, like, milk crate
snowshoes for you.
Thank you, Guy,
that'd be great.
And then you can have this.
Then you can go around
being 6'6".
Coming up on Christmas.
I like that.
So this is our mixture.
So it looks like, uh,
beef soup.
Then we bring it to a hard boil
and then we simmer it...
Mmm.
...for about
two and a half hours.
I like the flavor already.
-All right.
-Chili cheese and onions.
The chili goes on perfect.
Great combination.
WOMAN: Combination
and two up on one.
That has everything --
wanted the onions, ketchup.
-And mustard.
-Chili.
And the chili sauce,
and that's what makes it
taste the best.
I'm usually about
a three biter.
That's one.
Mmm!
That's great.
Nice and juicy dog.
Crazy meat concoction on top.
White onions perfect.
Bun's nice and steamed.
Wish I could live here.
You taste the hot dog.
You taste the onions.
You taste the chili.
Delicious.
It's the best hot dog
I've ever had.
FIERI: And you get it quick.
I need two up on one...
'Cause they got a code
all the room.
Three up on one,
hold the mustard.
Three hot dogs
for two people,
they say "three up on two."
So I'm gonna call them
out to you, okay?
Seven up three.
Seven up on three.
Two onion mustard.
No. Two hold the chili.
Huh?
You have to say
"hold the chili."
Maybe I just need to get --
I need to get some training.
If you want onion
and mustard on it,
then you say "hold the chili."
That way I know
it's onion and mustard.
So I don't have to say
"hold the chili"?
No. So if you just want
mustard and onion,
then you say
"hold the chili."
It's a lot easier...
Oh! Because it has mustard --
Ah! Okay, forget it then.
He wastes no time.
Two up on one or one up on two,
they have it out to you
in no time flat.
Andy, he would have
eight or nine hot dogs
lined up on his wrist
and arm,
nine of them done
in like 30 seconds.
I want 10.
I can't. The elbow joint's
right there.
Seven.
I can't do 10, Guy.
I can do eight.
You can do 12 now!
Up to my shoulder blade.
You graduated.
I haven't even taken it
to the collarbone
or the ear lobe yet.
There you go, John.
This is what Baltimore's
all about.
This place is a landmark.
It is a landmark.
It's a legend.
My mom came here.
My dad came here.
I'm here. One day
I'll bring my children up.
We are comfortable doing it
old school.
That's the kind of joint --
I want to eat where he cooks.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
♪ "Triple D" came to my city ♪
♪ Got me working here
every night and day ♪
♪ Got to get ready
for Mr. Guy Fieri ♪
[ Laughs ]
♪ Got to show him
how I do it my way ♪