Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
This trip...
Can I get
a drum roll, please?
...we're hitting up spots
where you can dive right in...
Whoo!
...and grab
all kinds of grub.
[ Imitates pirate ] Are you
serious about that?
Like a money Miami joint...
You feel like you're
on vacation right here.
FIERI: ...going out of the box
with the Cuban...
This is a game-winner
right here, man.
...a funky little pub
in North Carolina...
I like it.
...spinning gourmet
into their bar food.
This will blow
people's minds.
Plus, a taste of Chicago
in Arizona...
Come on, now!
...going deep
with their pizza...
[ Mouthful ]
Man, that's a big pie!
...and wicked with their sticks.
What part of your mouth
survives after you eat this?
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, when I think
of the term "snowbird,"
I'm thinking somebody
from New York City
that goes all the way down
to Florida.
But what about the people
from Chicago that come down to,
say, like here,
in Tucson, Arizona,
and they want some of
their hometown favorites,
like Italian beef
or deep-dish pizza?
Well, don't worry, there's a guy
that's here saving the day,
for the last 20 years.
This is Rocco's.
♪♪
We got a half a meatball
sandwich coming up.
You can't possibly come to
Tucson without going to Rocco's.
Large, thin sausage,
going in!
Best pizza, best wings.
Got a beef sandwich!
Rocco definitely makes it
feel like Chicago in here.
FIERI: And, yeah,
that's really his name --
Rocco DiGrazia,
a Tucson transplant
who's bringing a piece
of the Windy City
to sunny Arizona.
Do you get a lot of snowbirds
coming from Chicago
that are coming here and going,
"Oh, thank goodness"?
It's staggering.
So, are you known for your
thin or are you known
for your deep-dish?
We sell about
half of each.
Well, see,
I'm an all-thin guy,
but I hear that the deep-dish
you do is pretty gangster.
And it comes fully loaded.
Kitchen Sink going in!
It's called the Kitchen Sink
for a reason. [ Laughs ]
It's deep, it's hearty.
It's a full meal.
All right,
so let's make this.
DiGRAZIA: We're making some
deep-dish pizza dough.
High-gluten flour?
Yep.
[ Imitates pirate ]
Are you serious
about that?
Arr!
[ Laughs ]
Salt, sugar, yeast.
Water goes in all at once,
and canola oil.
Go for about three, four minutes
till it comes together?
What size portions?
20 ounces.
Really?
Yeah.
We're gonna do
a single proof?
24 hours
is the sweet spot.
Got to love
that yeast build-up.
Now, we're gonna make
our pizza sauce.
So, first, we got ground
tomatoes, peeled tomatoes.
Tomato paste, garlic,
light olive oil.
Chiffonade
of fresh basil.
Listen to you
with your chiffonade.
Dried oregano,
a little sugar.
Honey.
Dried basil.
Black pepper. We got salt,
and dried marjoram.
Gives it
a little fruity flavor.
Let it sit.
It gets better over a day.
Yeah, it does.
Then I oil my pan.
Oh, I like that move.
Now we're gonna roll
this out a little bit.
Toss it just
a little bit to size.
Halfway up the sides.
Yeah, it's called
the Kitchen Sink.
I assume
it's getting everything.
It's getting everything.
-So, this is mozz and provolone?
-Mozz and prov.
Hurry up, make the pizza
before I eat it all.
DiGRAZIA:
Flat meats first.
You don't read that
on every bumper sticker.
Cooked Italian sausage,
red onions,
green peppers,
mushrooms.
Squish it down
a little bit.
Whoa.
Fat ladle of sauce
on there.
Parmesan cheese.
Got it.
Use one of these things.
It's a heat sink.
This is going to grab heat
and put it in the center?
Right,
and in a deck oven,
this pizza will take
about 25 minutes.
Since we got
a conveyor oven,
we cook it
in about like 17.
Not bad.
All right,
so we got this baby.
Make sure
it's not sticking.
Pull away the pan.
We're ready to go.
Okay.
♪♪
So, the sauce
is on the top.
Where God intended it
for a deep-dish.
Because, otherwise,
it wouldn't crust up?
That's right.
From all the deep-dish
that I've had,
this is far more in balance
that it typically is.
'Cause this becomes
a little bit more al dente,
and I like crunchy veggies,
so that works for me.
The crust is great.
It's not all dough.
You got good yeast
to it.
The oil on the bottom of the pan
makes a nice crust to it.
That pizza sauce
is the real deal.
[ Mouthful ]
Man, that's a big pie!
All the way out in Tucson,
real-deal,
Chicago-style pizza
from a gangster.
It's so cheesy and delicious.
The sauce is amazing.
It's full of spice.
Very robust.
-The crust here is so good.
FIERI:
So, why not just have that?
Well, you can, with a big,
old pile of these babies.
SERVER:
Here's your hot sticks.
Hot sticks have the wing sauce
in the middle
of the pizza crust.
It's twisted and baked off.
You cannot beat the sauce.
The sauce is homemade, it's hot.
What are we
making next, buddy?
Making Lefty's
vinaigrette dressing.
Lefty's vinaigrette?
Yeah.
-Who is Lefty?
-It's my old drummer's mom.
Come on, now!
You're a musician, also?
-Yeah.
Playing drums in a punk-rock
band I'm in right now.
I would never
imagine.
So, what do you do
with this vinaigrette?
It's a component
of our famous wing sauce.
That's why --
-You -- No, no, whoa, wait.
The salad dressing is part
of the wing sauce?
Yeah.
All right, first,
we got canola oil,
extra virgin olive oil.
Red wine vinegar.
Okay.
Balsamic vinegar.
Got to have the garlic.
Ground black pepper,
dried oregano,
mustard powder.
-A little emulsification.
Basil, salt,
and the sugar,
and then the flaky
parsley goodness.
And you want it to sit overnight
so the dry herbs...
-Right, right, right.
-...blossom a little bit.
Works for me.
Now we're gonna build
the wing sauce.
First, we got
our hot sauce,
we got liquid margarine,
Lefty's vinaigrette,
ground jalapeños.
A lot of them.
Black pepper, garlic,
red pepper flakes.
Whoa!
And a bunch
of cayenne pepper.
-Are you really serious?
-Flame on, dude.
What part of your mouth
survives after you eat this?
You'll be enjoying
every minute of it.
Whoo!
And while you do all this,
you make some of the garlic --
what are the things you call
the bread, the twisty thing
in the middle --
[Mumbling]
Hot sticks.
The wing sauce thrown
on the dough,
twisted up,
run through the oven.
You got to try it
in the bleu cheese, though.
That completes
the picture of the dish.
♪♪
I love the crust of pizza.
It's my favorite thing.
When you can get spicy
pizza crust, you're winning.
♪♪
Wow!
Those are good.
That's the real deal.
Really unique to Rocco's.
I've never had breadsticks
like this anywhere else.
Who wouldn't want
breadsticks with that
amazing hot-wing sauce
inside of them?
What's the story
on the wings?
We par-cook them
through the oven.
Okay.
So, you render some of the fat,
you get them cooked.
That's right.
Then we fry them until
they're crispy and golden brown.
-Tossed in the sauce?
-Yep.
Coat them all up.
♪♪
Mm-hmm.
That's a great wing.
Really good texture.
Really good fry to it.
It's not dried out.
It's got a great sauce.
It's not
overwhelmingly hot.
Bleu cheese is right.
I got any right there?
[ Laughs ]
Just right.
Chicken wings,
they're my favorite.
Perfect, crispy wings,
hot sauce. The best.
Spaghetti with meatballs,
coming up!
I always come back to Rocco's,
'cause I know
I can get a really solid meal.
Never leaves me unsatisfied.
A punk-rock drummer
from Chicago
in a funky,
little joint.
I mean, you are
representing simple food,
made the right way,
a lot of integrity.
Well done.
Thanks, Guy.
FIERI: Up next,
it's game time in Miami...
That's awesome, brother.
I dig it.
...where Coach Gruden's
taking the field...
You're gonna be busy
for the day, Coach.
...for some Cuban
that's hard to beat.
I love this job.
You got it made, man.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Miami's Little Havana --
[ Engine revs ]
Hey, Coach,
enough on the engine.
...to check out a joint
where a husband-and-wife team --
[ Engine revs ]
Dude,
you're killin' me.
A husband-and-wife team
are serving up
some Cuban food elevated
to another level.
Whoo!
Coach, enough!
Are you hungry?
Come on,
Coach Gruden.
This is
Doce Provisions.
Awesome, but after we eat,
we got to do
some burnouts
in this Camaro.
You're killin' me.
♪♪
-Short rib taco up.
-That's like home cooking.
The food is awesome.
You can't go wrong.
MAN: The plantains working?
I haven't tried anything
like these in Miami.
It's not your typical Cuban.
FIERI: Which is all part
of the strategy
for owner Justin Sherrer
and his wife, Lisetty Llampalla,
to bring something different,
but still celebrate
Little Havana.
SHERRER:
I love the neighborhood,
I love the culture.
My wife's Cuban.
I love Cuban food.
And their Cuban food
is all about big flavors
breaking out
on a pretty small menu.
What do we got,
maybe 15 items, if?
And when you have
somebody
that's doing those few items,
you can bet it's because
each one of those items
he's vetted out.
It's kind of like having only
15 plays in your playbook.
People know what they're getting
when they come in here.
It's a perfect menu.
It's just what you want.
SERVER:
Chorizo croquettes.
The chorizo croquettes,
he's thinking
outside of the box.
Most croquettes
are just soft.
This actually
has a crunch to it.
So, croquettes --
let's get into this.
If you're in Miami and you
don't have a good croquette
on the menu,
you know, like...
And there are more
bad croquettes
than there are good croquettes.
-A lot.
I mean, I'm getting
hungry here.
Let's go.
Butter, garlic.
Boom.
Shallot. Next going in
is the bacon.
What I do is take
the Miami Smokers'
bacon, puree it.
Miami Smokers is a "Triple D"
joint we did years ago.
Let's throw Coach in.
Let's throw him in the pit.
Step right
over here, man.
A little nervous
right here, Justin.
-Nope.
-This is my first time in a --
"My first time on Food Network
and now I got to cook."
A little bit
different than
the oatmeal I cook
back at my house.
SHERRER:
Now, drop your chorizo.
Ground, smoked pork.
It gets hot working
over the stove.
It's like calling the plays
on a third down.
With a bad
offensive line.
I mean, it's hot, man.
[ Laughs ]
Right on. So, yeah,
add some milk,
put your heavy cream
right there.
Bring that to a boil.
More house seasoning.
Okay, and what do we have
in our house seasoning here?
A little bit -- just paprika,
Sazón, salt.
Sazón.
Smoked paprika.
You got a little sweet
in there. Mmm.
Yep.
We're gonna drop
some flour in there.
Once it's tightened
up, we're gonna let it
cool on a sheet tray,
just enough to where
we can put it in a bag.
I'm gonna pipe it out
into a log, score them.
Got it.
We're gonna cool them
in the cooler,
hen we're gonna pop them
and bread them.
We're just gonna use egg wash
and our seasoned bread crumbs.
Okay, you're gonna be busy
for the day, Coach.
Yeah,
I'll tell you.
All right,
so what are we making?
Sauce for
the croquettes.
Dijon mustard,
Kewpie mayonnaise.
Japanese mayonnaise --
really fatty, really thick.
I mean, you could repair
a hole in your wall
in college with that.
That and a little bit of flour.
I could've used
some Kewpie.
Fresh lime juice,
kosher salt.
Let's fry up the croquette
and get this done.
♪♪
We're gonna drop our mustard
on the plate,
frisée and a couple pickles
on there.
The croquettes.
It's a nice
presentation.
And garnish with
some Cotija cheese.
All right, Coach,
I'm gonna let you in first.
Oh, it's my honor.
Okay, now this,
ladies and gentlemen,
is a very
important moment.
Can I get
a drum roll, please?
[ Drum roll plays ]
That's some
magical stuff.
The crunchiness.
It's firm, but it's moist,
but it's not wet.
Coach picked
it out perfectly,
is that it is so moist
without being soggy,
it's so rich with the bacon
coming in with the chorizo
and coming in
with the loin -- rich city.
This Dijonnaise
is perfect.
Brilliant how you have
all these ingredients
that go into one
of these little guys.
It's a heck of a job.
Chorizo croquettes.
The croquettes are delicious.
They pack a flavorful punch.
It's like this symphony
of flavors.
Short rib burger.
Doce is actually one
of my favorite places
down here in Little Havana.
Where'd the name
come from?
I was sitting here,
thinking about a name,
I looked up
at the sign outside
and I saw 12, and I said,
"How about Doce?"
That's awesome, brother.
I dig it.
Doce's a great place.
It's a quaint place.
MAN:
It has a very relaxed ambiance.
Everything is very,
very artistic.
I mean, this place just
makes you want to come in.
Coach Gruden and I hanging out
at Doce, here in Little Havana.
When we come back, we're
gonna make something else?
Masa de puerco chinos.
Masa de puerco --
fried rice.
It's got, like, the pork chunks
on top, the fried plantains.
This is something
I would definitely order
every single time I'm here.
You do not
want to miss this.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
♪♪
Here we are
back at Doce's.
My man, Guy.
We got Justin, the chef.
What are we
doing right here?
You like that?
It was awesome!
I'm so worried
about my job future
because I cannot
call football at all!
FIERI: But I do know
how to find the all-stars,
like this Latin-fusion joint
in Miami's Little Havana,
and I'm teaming up
with Coach Jon Gruden
to check out their game plan.
Bacon-egg pad Thai up.
He takes a dish
that isn't traditionally
like a very Hispanic dish,
and then adds
Hispanic components to it.
So, like the fried rice.
Masa de puerco chino.
You've got a little bit
of the sweet
and a little bit of the Asian.
What are we
putting together here?
Our Masa
de puerco chino --
fried pork tossed into
homemade sweet chili sauce
on top of a fried rice
with sweet plantains.
Basically,
we salted this overnight.
Put some holes
in this guy.
Okay.
These garlic cloves are
gonna sit inside of there.
Stud it up.
First, we'll mix it
all together here --
the sour orange,
fresh lime juice, cumin.
Throw some bay leaf
in there.
I just, you know,
give it a rub
and then put
the garlic in there.
That garlic is just gonna
bleed right over there.
Get right
into there, yeah.
350, 400, 5 to 6 hours,
and in the meantime,
we'll work on
the pineapple confit?
Yes, sir.
Dig it.
Blended oil,
bell peppers.
Add a little salt.
Pineapple.
A little bit of sugar
and a little bit
of togarashi seasoning.
Interesting.
The togarashi playing into a
little bit of this Asian fusion.
We're just gonna cook this down
for about 15, 20 minutes,
and that's what we toss
with our pork.
And next?
We're gonna make
our sweet chili sauce.
Okay.
So, we're gonna start
with a little water.
We got
the red bell peppers,
crushed garlic,
crushed red pepper.
We're gonna puree this.
-Okay.
Start with rice vinegar,
sugar, pepper puree.
Cook for about
10, 15 minutes.
And now, we're gonna make
our fried rice.
Hit it.
Green onions,
bell peppers in there.
Cold rice.
Tamarind
fried-rice sauce.
So, the tamarind pot has
this nice sourness to it
in a lot of Asian food.
Then we're gonna add
our bean sprouts.
Look how beautiful
that is.
Now we're gonna fry
the plantains and pork.
Okay.
We're gonna add
our pineapple confit.
-The sweet chili sauce you made.
-Give it a little squeeze.
Now we're gonna plate
our rice, pork here.
Wouldn't be Miami
without sweet plantains.
Okay.
And a little frisée
and pickled pepper.
Gorgeous, man.
Just gorgeous.
Coach.
Thank you.
♪♪
You feel like you're
on vacation right here.
I love this job.
You got it made, man.
[ Laughs ]
What's your one loss, Guy?
Do you lose any?
The attention
that you put to the pork
so it's nice and tender,
and then you put
that little bit of fry
on the outside of it
so you get tender in the middle,
and you get that nice crisp.
You put the sweet plantain
next to it,
you're getting
all of these counterbalances.
You're getting sour,
and you're getting sweet,
and you're getting salty,
and you're getting crunchy,
and you're getting soft.
It's dynamite, bro.
That's the goal.
[ Laughs ]
SERVER:
Masa de puerco chino.
The plantains
are cooked perfectly,
the pork has that little
crunchy exterior.
Everything is just
phenomenal and delicious.
Enjoy, guys.
Some of the best food in Miami.
This is game-winner,
right here, man. Well done.
Great job, Justin.
Thank you.
Thanks, Coach.
I loved it, man.
Appreciate it, brother.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Wilmington, North Carolina...
Come on down for some duck
fancy-wing and duck l'orange.
What looks like
your typical bar bites...
I'd pass out
eating that.
...are way more
than you bargained for.
"Delicious"
is an understatement.
And these are
the croquettes that beat
the legendary
Richard Hales.
the chef
from Sakaya Kitchen?
SHERRER: I think
I got lucky.
-[ Laughs ]
-Oh, man. How you doing, bro?
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
FIERI: So, I'm here
in historic downtown
Wilmington, North Carolina.
Beautiful place, and you're
right in the middle of it all.
All kinds of restaurants,
you got the river walk,
and you got big decisions.
Where are you gonna eat?
Well, I've heard from some
locals, "You got to check out
this little place where you got
to expect the wait,
'cause they only got 40 seats,"
and it's well worth it,
'cause this is
The Fork-N-Cork.
♪♪
Got a fonduta
and some wings, Table 4!
It's more of a dining experience
that somewhere just to go eat.
Got a Reuben wearing fries!
You can count
on the food being good,
you can count
on the people being friendly.
FIERI: And a lot of folks count
on self-made chef James Smith
to give their taste buds
a run for their money.
I wanted to take all the food
you ate when you were in college
and elevate it
with better ingredients,
and then take some
fine-dining menu items
and kind of dumb
them down and --
Bar-ify them?
Yeah.
Okay.
SERVER: Duck wings.
You can go anyplace in town
and get chicken wings.
Confit duck wings with
habanero orange marmalade.
You can't beat them.
-So, what are we making first?
All right, we're gonna do
our duck confit wings,
just the drumettes.
A little bit
of kosher salt, sugar.
Black peppercorns.
Black pepper, okay.
Juniper berries.
Juniper's got to play
in there somewhere.
Fresh garlic
and fresh thyme.
Cover it
with the duck fat.
At what temp
and how long?
275 for about
4, 4 1/2 hours.
Let them cool
in the duck fat.
And then pull them out,
'cause we're gonna fry 'em.
Corn starch first.
Okay.
And what are we
serving them with?
-Habanero orange sauce.
-Okay.
-And a hot honey garlic.
-Bring it.
We're doing
our hot honey garlic sauce.
Butter, a little bit
of garlic,
red chili flake.
Whoa, a lot of it.
And then just
a little bit of honey.
All right, sugar.
Let it cook down
for about 10, 15 minutes.
-And that's all she wrote.
-Then it'll be ready to go.
I like it.
Next one's gonna be...?
Orange habanero
marmalade.
Orange marmalade.
Orange habanero --
Is it
orange habanero...
marmalade?
Marmalade.
Come on down for the jazz
fingers. They're fantastic.
We've got our orange marmalade,
habanero sauce.
-Nothing wrong with this.
-Nothing wrong with that.
Fresh ground pepper,
kosher salt.
And then, we're just
gonna whisk that together.
I like it.
All right, we've pulled
our wings out of the fryer.
I don't think we've ever seen
duck wings on "Triple D."
Hot honey garlic.
-Give them a little coating.
Right.
And then we've got
our orange habanero.
What's your favorite
of the two?
I love them both.
♪♪
A duck wing.
That is so fantastic.
It's got a richness to it,
got great texture.
So, what's your favorite?
I think the honey.
It's got good heat,
not really thick.
That right there.
Habanero orange sauce.
Duck l'orange,
with some attitude,
and duck fancy-wing.
Come on down for some duck
fancy-wing and duck l'orange.
SERVER:
And I have your duck wings.
WOMAN: It's more tender than
a regular chicken wing.
It's just excellent.
The honey garlic sauce is light
and a little bit spicy.
That orange flavor. Whew,
it has a lot of kick to it.
How do you describe
the place to folks,
when you're telling them
about coming down here?
I always tell people
who've never been here before
you can't go wrong
with the burger.
FIERI: Especially one
that's personalized.
Tell me about how
the Ava burger came about.
He asked me
if I wanted my own burger,
and I said yes.
Okay.
I told him
that I wanted bacon.
So, you would've been happy
if the whole Ava burger
was just
a giant bacon burger?
I like my burger.
You should like your burger
when it's named after you.
And beyond the burger,
this place definitely
raises the bar on bar food.
Wellington bites,
Table 2!
Kind of like getting a steak as
an appetizer, all in one bite.
Well, we're gonna
get into something now
that we've never seen
on "Triple D" --
a Wellington bite?
Beef Wellington.
We've just miniaturized it.
Turned it into bar food.
Fantastic.
We're gonna make
our mushroom duxelle.
A little bit
of olive oil,
butter,
diced-up prosciutto,
mushrooms -- creminis.
Cremini's my favorite.
Fresh thyme, a little bit
of salt and pepper.
We're gonna go ahead and let
this render 15, 20 minutes.
And let it cool
so we can stuff it.
Absolutely.
I like the way
he's rolling.
We're gonna
cube up some fillet,
typically used
for your Wellington.
Seasoned with a little salt
and pepper.
Now we've got
our mushroom duxelle.
Add a little bit
of Dijon mustard,
a little bit
of goose-liver pâté.
In a bar.
And we're just gonna mix
this just so you have
a nice, smooth paste.
Okay.
Spray our sheet tray.
Add our puff pastry,
our duxelle mix,
one cube each.
And then we're just
gonna wrap these up,
little Christmas
present-style.
So, what everybody
loves about beef Wellington is,
they love
the crust anyways.
And the nice little ratio
he's made here
gives you the chance
you're gonna get great puff,
nice little piece
of fillet inside.
We're gonna go in
and add
a little egg wash
just to get them nice
and brown. Perfect.
We're going at 425
for about 10 minutes.
Okay.
And we're making our
port wine cherry sauce.
Dig it.
-Start with our port wine.
-A lot of dried cherries.
A little white sugar,
a little bit
of fresh rosemary,
fresh-ground
black pepper.
And we're gonna bring that
to a simmer.
We're gonna add
a little bit of butter,
then we're gonna hit it
with the boat motor.
-Let's put it together, man.
-All right.
Toasty and brown
Wellington bites.
Look at that.
It's very luxurious.
That's the one.
Mmm!
Delicious.
This will blow
people's minds.
That was the plan.
I'm serious.
I enjoy it
so much more because --
You get all
the good parts.
The pastry.
That's where you're at.
The duxelle is delish.
I'd pass out
eating that.
"Delicious"
is an understatement.
Mmm!
Outstanding.
Awesome.
Jay, your personal favorite,
the Wellington bites.
MAN: What's there not to like
about medium-rare fillet
and a puff pastry?
You get your fix, because
it is a very rich dish.
It's very unique
and it's delicious.
Short rib mac!
Hot chicken, french fries!
FIERI: I've been to some
funky little joints,
but for 40 seats and,
I don't know, six tables,
that's -- it's
a pretty neat place.
You always know that it's gonna
be really, really good.
It's remarkable.
You deserve all the recognition
you're getting.
Well, thank you very much.
I appreciate that.
Thank you, man.
Congrats.
Was that a road trip
or what?
But don't worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
♪♪
GRUMAN:
I can't believe I'm sitting
in this ride, man.
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
Where's Guy at?
Tell him I'm leaving.
Yeah!