Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
La-la-la-la-la-la.
We're digging into
tasty tradition...
What have you got me into?
...and killer cultural cuisines.
Oh!
Like an old-school cafeteria
in Chicago...
All right,
to the cashier, it is.
...dishing out deli favorites
since the 1940s...
-Can I get some of this to go?
-Of course.
60 pounds, please.
...and a unique Seattle spot...
Holy moly.
...hand-making righteous
Russian recipes.
If you can come down here
and get this flavor bomb.
...plus, a real-deal Hawaiian
hangout...
This is how you do it?
...serving up an authentic
island experience.
My name's Guy Fieri,
and that's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
I have said it once.
I will say it again.
Chicago's one of my favorite
food towns,
and this is one
of the reasons why.
I'm here, on the South Loop,
to check out a joint
that's been serving up
old-school deli since 1942.
This is the one and only
Manny's Cafeteria & Deli.
♪♪
Pastrami Reuben.
This is Chicago.
Can I have the beef stew?
I've been coming to Manny's
for about 45 years.
It's the best.
I need two knishes,
please.
It's a really traditional
Jewish deli menu.
FIERI: And a really old-school
cafeteria.
I can't take credit for it.
We've been doing the things
the same way since we opened.
Which is over 75 years ago,
by Dan Raskin's great-grandpa.
And together with his parents,
Ken and Patti,
they're dishing up four
generations of family heritage.
Potato pancake and matzo bowl.
WOMAN: There's no question
why it's been here so long.
It's the place to come
if you're in Chicago.
If I'm gonna have a deli
sandwich, I'm coming to Manny's.
Pastrami Reuben.
The pastrami itself is seasoned
to perfection,
and they just stack it on there,
nice and high for you.
You make real-deal pastrami?
The real deal.
Our pastrami and corned beef
are our two most popular items.
Out of the whole thing?
Out of everything, yeah.
How many pounds do you
go through a month?
Probably about
40,000 pounds.
40,000 pounds
of pastrami a month?
I'm serious.
All right.
Let's go, pastrami.
We are making a brine.
We're gonna start
with our water.
We have kosher salt, brown
sugar, garlic, curing salt.
Mix it really well.
Let this all
come to a boil?
For 30 minutes.
Let it cool.
Now, we're gonna take our brine
and secure our beef navel.
Beef navel?
Yeah.
Not this kind of navel?
You got it.
Yeah.
You ever been
to the navel academy?
[ Crickets chirping ]
All right, how long's
it gonna marinate?
5 days.
Now we're gonna go
with the dry rub?
Yep.
We got brown sugar, coriander...
A whole bunch of it.
A whole bunch.
Allspice.
Black pepper, mustard,
garlic powder.
So you grab the navel.
There's so many jokes
I want to make about the navel.
And then we're gonna mix
the spices in.
Holy moly.
And then bake it
in the oven.
How long?
60 to 80 minutes.
Sliced to order.
Sliced to order?
You got it.
Oh!
♪♪
FIERI:
But we got to wait to dig in,
'cause there's a lot more
to load up on at this deli line.
There's a salad bar, there's
bagels, knishes, matzo ball.
I mean, you name it,
you got it.
We got it.
Crazy.
MAN: You can't beat the quality
of food here at Manny's.
It's just a wonderful
Chicago experience.
You'll see so much history
on the walls.
So many politicians
and celebrities come here.
You're favorite thing
on the menu?
My favorite thing
is the stuffed cabbage.
Stuffed cabbage.
The cabbage roll is delicious.
The meat is a really good blend
of seasonings and rice,
and it goes really well
with the sauce.
A little bit of sweet,
a little bit of sour,
but it's not overpowering.
So we're making
cabbage rolls?
Correct. We're gonna be, first,
boiling our cabbage heads.
Got you, there.
Now we're gonna make
the sauce for it.
Sauce?
Oil, our onion, garlic,
water, salt...
White pepper?
Sugar, tomato puree.
And then, we do
our golden raisins.
Raisins get
cooked right in?
Cooked right in.
And we're gonna add citric acid.
Let it cook down.
And last but not least...
We're gonna make
the meat filling.
80/20 ground beef,
grinding the mat in-house.
We're gonna add our water,
in-house ground bread crumbs,
garlic powder,
kosher salt,
white pepper,
diced green pepper, white rice.
The rice
is already cooked.
Sometimes when you cook cabbage
leaves and you use raw rice,
you have to add a liquid to it,
which it absorbs.
I've seen it both ways.
We have ground onion.
And a little binder
for some egg.
To keep it all together.
Stop.
Wait a second.
Did you guys
not catch that?
You guys are in your
"Triple D" coma.
Back that up.
And a little binder
for some egg.
What I meant to say was,
"A little egg for some binder."
So, you're gonna mix
this all together
and bring the cabbage out.
And try to find
the biggest ones we can get.
You have to.
We're gonna put three pieces
all together.
Really?
Even though they're big.
Yes.
And then, we're gonna take
a big handful of meat...
Oh!
...and make the meatball
out of it,
lay it right in the center,
fold over the sides.
Okay.
Make sure it's nice
and tight,
and then put it
right in the pan.
Ladle over the sauce?
Yep.
Foil, oven, eat --
my motto.
SERVER: Stuffed cabbage.
The cabbage roll,
it's like Sunday dinner,
kind of all wrapped up
on one plate.
FIERI: But don't think
you can just stick
to one plate at this joint.
They know
what they're doing.
There's no way you can get
through that whole line
without picking
a few things.
So, you're going out
with a tray like this.
♪♪
All right, to the cashier,
it is.
Okay, mac and cheese,
with bucatini.
You can taste how long you guys
have been doing it.
Have you guys changed
any of the recipes
since you've started?
That was the one thing
my dad told me,
"Don't change anything."
Oh, dude.
Short rib is dynamite.
So let's talk about this.
That's good beef stew.
What is this, pepper steak?
Pepper steak.
Pepper steak's great,
falls off the bone.
That's a beef knish.
That's ridiculous.
So people can come in,
load it up like
I'm doing it,
or they can just come in
and get one item,
get it to go?
Yeah, you can eat here, to go,
delivered, whatever you want.
You deliver?
Of course.
Okay, I live in Santa Rosa,
California.
I want it hot, though,
when you get there.
The matzo ball soup.
Dynamite.
Stuffed cabbage.
That's really good.
Thanks.
That sweet-and-sour raisin sauce
that goes over the top of it
makes everything
worth it.
The cabbage just melts
in your mouth.
I've had a lot
of stuffed cabbage.
That ranks really high.
All right,
last but not least.
The navel's
nice and lean.
You get a little bit
of fat to it,
but not an imbalance
of fat.
It's this bark that you have
on the outside of it,
with the pepper and the
coriander, that really makes it.
That's the bite,
right there.
Can I get some of this
to go?
Of course.
60 pounds, please.
♪♪
Pastrami Reuben and a knish.
This is my buddy
Armando from...
La Scarola.
...one of my favorite
restaurants in Chicago.
There's great sandwiches
in this town.
For the best pastrami
and corned beef, you come here.
It's a landmark --
definitely a landmark.
I can only imagine the
characters that come through,
the things they order,
you know,
the energy
that goes on in this place.
It's got to be
like a machine.
Yeah.
Like a big,
gigantic heartbeat.
It's very fun.
Nicely done, friend.
FIERI: Up next, an island
immersion in Kona...
All right, this is
how we get it done?
...serving up the most
traditional Hawaiian dishes...
You're looking for that
cultural experience,
this is the experience.
...that you have to eat
to believe.
This is the worst-looking thing
I've ever had
on "Triple D,"
and it tastes fantastic.
♪♪
So I'm here on the Big Island
of Hawaii, hanging out
with one of my favorite poke
chefs from Umekes, Chef Nakoa.
Now, listen, Chef,
I shot that joint,
Foster's Kitchen,
I shot that joint.
That's Island Lava Java.
And where are you
taking me?
Got to get you an Hawaiian
cultural experience.
Okay.
Welcome to Kanaka Kava.
♪♪
A little pork.
This is the only place
in town
that you find
real Hawaiian food.
Laulau plate.
WOMAN: It's really fresh.
Most of it's grown here,
on the Island.
How's everything?
When I first stumbled upon
this place,
the owner
was talking to people
about Hawaiian history
and Hawaiian culture.
FIERI: And that local guru
is Zack Gibson,
who's been repping the Hawaiian
culture at this chill
gathering spot for 17 years.
FIERI: In the middle of
the heavy tourist area...
Yep.
...you've got
a spiritual energy,
chill factor.
Yeah..
You got your own little program
going, man.
Yeah, it's about being spiritual
Hawaiian down here, in town,
showing it as Hawaiian, still.
We are Hawaiian.
He's so much more Hawaiian
than you.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: And a taste of Hawaii
isn't complete without this
straight-from-the-sea
island staple.
The poke.
It's relatively traditional
Hawaiian poke,
so they got the seaweed
and the kukui nut in there,
and it's just delicious.
Let's talk about the poke.
This is the main ingredient --
the raw fish.
We're gonna trim
this baby up.
I do like about 3/4-inch,
1/2-inch pieces.
Yeah.
Next up, we're gonna start
putting in the ingredients.
I like to put in the ogo first.
We'll take some of this out.
Didn't we use ogo when we made
poke at your place?
Yep.
Ogo's super popular
and tastes like the sea.
Okay.
So, for our traditional
poke,
you need the seaweed and you
need this, the kukui nut.
These are Kula onions,
a sweet onion.
Cucumber, with the middles
taken out
so it doesn't
get all watery.
Okay.
Hawaiian salt.
That should go directly
on the fish.
Chili pepper water, a little bit
of chili peppers, dried, garlic.
He's crushing it,
over here.
Sesame oil.
Looks good, Zack.
Okay, brother.
Okay, this is how
we get it done?
Give it a try.
♪♪
Better than mine?
[ Laughs ]
Here's the interesting
thing.
Similar ingredients,
completely
different flavor.
Mm-hmm.
It's light...
It's like a salad.
...it's fresh.
The Hawaiian sea salt
in there,
that's the
pièce de résistance.
Yeah, it's the key.
Great ahi.
A little bit of chili flake.
Nothing's overpowering
the flavor of the, uh --
of the ahi, itself.
Right.
When you make poke, generally,
you like the tuna
to be the star
of the dish...
Right.
...not all the extra
ingredients.
Right. Dude, I got to be honest
with you,
and I'm saying it in front
of one of the poke masters.
That poke is spot-on.
Thank you, guys, very much.
Awesome.
Got poke.
The poke here
is absolutely amazing.
It's got this nice balance
and crunchiness
between the little bits
of the ogo seaweed,
and then, cucumbers
and sweet onions.
Fresh fish -- can't get
any better than that.
Breadfruit for Mike.
The food's wonderful.
It's difficult to find
some of the traditional
Hawaiian food items at,
even, other Hawaiian food
places in town.
GIBSON: A pupu platter.
The pupu platter has
a little bit of everything.
All of them are
originally the plants
that the Polynesians
brought over here,
and the food that they hunt.
It's definitely a true
Hawaiian experience.
That's a pupu platter.
Okay.
This is the kalua pork,
these are the purple
sweet potatoes,
here's our delicious poke,
this is poi,
and her's our
signature dish.
That's squid luau, which is
the taro leaves with octopus,
coconut milk
and some sweetener.
What have you
got me into?
♪♪
That's my grandma's recipe.
How's that?
Bro, this is the
worst-looking thing
I've ever had
on "Triple D,"
and it tastes fantastic.
Yeah.
If you just get past the fact
that it's blended frog,
it's delicious.
[ Laughing ]
It's octopus.
It is delicious.
So, you could come
and just eat
the whole pupu platter
to yourself,
or you split that
with a few people.
What a trip.
Pupu platter's up.
If you're a tourist,
coming to Hawaii and you want
to taste Hawaiian food,
get the pupu platter.
What is the --
the blended frog, again?
Well, it's actually
squid luau.
It is...
outstanding.
It is outstanding.
You know, we were raised
on this kind of food.
This is tucked away,
in the back,
in the middle
of the tourist area,
but yet,
it's the locals' cool hang?
That's right.
You got to know.
Got the laulau, with some ulu
and some kalua pork.
FIERI: You're looking for
that cultural experience,
and you're coming
to the Island,
this is the experience --
coming and talking to you.
Come with an open mind,
and you're gonna have
a great experience.
Yeah.
You're crushing it.
What a pleasure, man.
Aloha.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, in Seattle...
Hot.
...a piroshki paradise...
This is fantastic.
...not taking any shortcuts with
their Eastern-European eats.
There has got to be
an easier way to do this.
Towel.
Oh. Sorry, sorry.
Taking care of you.
Thanks, bud.
[ Laughs ]
Little more pressure.
♪♪
I'm here in downtown Seattle,
Washington,
and I'm looking
for a piroshki place.
Now there's a lot of them
around here,
but this one,
they're doing things
just a little bit different.
All right,
so this is the place.
I can't park here,
so you go inside.
It's right there.
It's called Piroshki on 3rd.
♪♪
I have a smoked salmon
and cream cheese piroshki to go.
Everything's fresh-made,
in-house.
Your stuffed cabbage
and your solyanka.
I come from Kazakhstan,
a Russian-Ukrainian family.
I close my eyes, I can't tell
the difference
if I'm eating at home
or if I'm eating over here.
What can I get for you today?
FIERI: Even though this joint
serves up Russian specialities,
chef and owner Alyssa Anderson
comes from a completely
different
set of GPS coordinates.
Where are you from,
originally?
I'm from the Philippines.
Holy moly.
How'd you get from
the Philippines
to the United States?
I got an internship
at a hotel...
Okay.
...from culinary school.
FIERI: From there,
she moved to Seattle,
got married and became
a piroshki-making pro
when she bought this place
from retiring owners.
I have a ham
and cheese piroshki.
What are piroshkies?
They're pretty much like
Russian pockets.
All different types of filling,
wrapped in a crust.
Have you brought
any of your
Filipino influence
into piroshkies?
Yes.
I made this "Asado" piroshki.
The filling originated
from the Philippines.
SERVER: Garlic, beef "Asado"
piroshki, for here.
There's kind
of a sweet flavor to it,
which is unusual
in Russian piroshki.
All right, well,
let's get into it.
So we start
with the dough.
Yeast, water and sugar, then
we add some eggs, sour cream.
Okay.
Melted butter,
and then we have milk.
Next?
Sugar and I add the flour.
♪♪
And, at the end,
just add some oil.
So, when it pulls from the bowl,
it'll be done,
you'll bring it out,
it'll proof for 2 hours.
Yeah.
We keep it here, in the bowl.
Oh, it proofs
right in the bowl?
Yeah.
Right here?
Yeah. Right here.
Right here, right now,
at Piroshki's on 3rd?
Yes. Exactly.
I lent the tag line.
So, while that's proofing,
we'll go ahead
and make the filing?
Or do we go out
and play racquetball?
Make the fillings.
[ Laughs ]
So we start with the sauce --
sugar, Filipino soy sauce.
Filipino soy sauce?
It's like sweet soy sauce.
Hoisin, oyster sauce.
Oyster sauce is big
in Filipino food?
Yeah, because we have
some Chinese influences.
And then I add some chopped
onions, add some minced garlic.
Some minced garlic?
Chopped beef.
Eye of the round?
Yeah.
So that's gonna cook down.
Add the sauce.
The soy sauce, oyster sauce,
hoisin.
I could eat that
in a flip-flop.
Haven't heard that in a while,
have you?
[ Laughs ]
So that cooks down,
add a little corn starch to it,
tightens up,
let it cool...
Yeah.
...and then we'll use that
for the filling.
Yes.
So the dough is proofed,
portioned out.
I got to introduce you
to the world of a sheeter.
We like everything
old-fashioned here.
I have the filling here.
Whoa!
No wonder
they only order one.
And then fold it into
a triangle shape.
We've tried to do them
in different shapes.
Oh, so you can tell
what they are.
Yeah.
'Cause it would be awkward
if someone comes in and goes,
"I'll one of the "Asado" ones,
and you're like, "Uh...
that's 'Asado.'
That's a good one."
And are we gonna glaze
these with anything on top?
Yes, we're putting egg
wash on it.
You pop it in the oven,
what temperature?
350.
And that will go
for how long?
20 minutes.
Our piroshkies are ready.
It's a gorgeous piroshki.
Thank you.
♪♪
Wow.
It's got the buttery crust,
it's got awesome texture
on the outside.
Maybe it's because
of the egg wash.
There's enough structure
inside of the dough
that supports
the rich filling,
because the filling's got
a little sweet.
You get a little soy,
you get that hoisin, oyster.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
You can come down here
and get this flavor bomb.
I mean, this thing is...
mmm, really good.
Nice job.
I have a garlic, beef "Asado"
piroshki for here.
The meat is really tender.
It melts right in your mouth.
And I'm from the Philippines.
This remind you of home?
Absolutely.
The flavors
and the textures?
The flavors.
Just the right amount of spice,
and it just brings me home.
And if you're looking for
more traditional piroshki...
I have a beef and cabbage.
FIERI: ...this joint has
20 different kinds.
The hardest thing to do
when you come in
is to figure out which
piroshki you're gonna choose.
Smoked turkey piroshki.
It's really great to come in
and see the ladies making them.
When you bought the business,
you inherited a couple grandmas.
ANDERSON:
Yeah, the babushkas.
So, a couple ladies
that had been working here
for how many years?
For 20 years.
Pretty much since
they came to America.
And where'd
they come from?
From Romania.
My babushkas
can do everything.
So, here's the deal.
We're hanging out at Piroshki
on 3rd, in Seattle, Washington.
FIERI: But even though
piroshki's in the name,
all kinds of Eastern-European
dishes are their game.
Pelmeni soup for you.
Pelmeni is a chicken
dumpling soup.
It's got sour cream and dill.
It's great.
FIERI: And that's what we're
digging into when we come back.
We'll see you in a little bit.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're hanging out
at Piroshki on 3rd,
in Seattle, Washington.
We've been making piroshkies.
This is hand-done work.
And this scratch-made
Russian menu
is an international labor
of love by Filipino chef
and owner Alyssa Anderson
and her Eastern-European staff.
ANDERSON: I have a chicken
pot pie for here.
MAN: I like to come in here
and get fresh-baked bread,
fresh-baked piroshkies,
and their fresh-made soup's
pretty bomb.
SERVER:
Pelmeni soup for you.
Pelmeni soup is dumplings
with the ground-chicken
meatballs in them.
There's a lot of herbs in it.
It's a lot of flavor.
We're making
the Pelmeni soup.
Peal-Pelmeni?
Pelmeni.
Since you can't keep up
with the Filipino words,
I barely handle English.
That's Russian.
All right, so, in Russian,
what does "Pelmeni" mean?
Little dumplings.
First, we're gonna
grind the chicken.
Thighs?
Yeah.
La-la-la-la-la-la.
All right.
And then, we add
some ground onions,
then add some salt
and pepper.
That's all it is
to the filling?
Yes.
It's very simple.
And the dough that we're
gonna use for this is...?
Dumpling dough.
It's made out of flour,
milk, eggs...
Not the same dough that we used
for the piroshki?
No.
No yeast.
Got it.
Place it here,
into our special mold.
Wait, wait, wait.
It's like
nine-finger baling.
That's culinary gangster,
right there.
Hey, what up, drag?
Then, we take our chicken
and just start filling the gaps.
You do this every day?
Yeah. Every day.
Are we putting
a layer on top?
Yes, and then I'm gonna take
a bigger rolling pin.
Pushing down on it
the whole time,
until it cuts
all the way through?
Yes.
So, now,
you peel all that away.
Yes.
There has got to be
an easier way to do this.
We're going to boil them
in the chicken stock.
So, a very simple
chicken stock.
Yes.
Add mushrooms, tomatoes...
A little fresh dill.
And then, when it starts
boiling, we add our pelmeni.
So, 15 of the dumplings
per order?
Yes.
So how long does that
take to cook?
About 5 to 10 minutes.
We add some pepper.
It adds more heat to it.
Then we add the sour cream
on top and some more dill.
Bet you those aren't hot.
♪♪
Hot.
Order on Thursday,
pick it up Friday morning.
It'll be cooled
down enough.
The broth is simple,
the dill is great,
the sour cream's
this nice, little, silky foil,
but the dumpling, itself,
with the ground chicken,
that thigh meat
and the onion...
♪♪
Mmm. Mmm.
...the dumplings
are ridonculous.
I came here
for the piroshki.
They're dynamite, but this soup
is stealing the show.
Thank you.
Mmm.
ANDERSON: I have a pelmeni
for here, please.
Have to have very, you know,
thin dough,
that's think enough
to keep the meat,
but also, not too thin
so it doesn't fall apart.
Delicious dumplings,
and it really has this authentic
Eastern-European flavor.
Amazing.
I have a stuffed cabbage
for here, please.
I'm Polish heritage, and these
are very similar to Russian,
Polish food, so, this is like
a taste of home for me.
You spend a lot of time
at this.
Yes.
Everything's made with love.
No, everything's
made by hand.
This is fantastic.
I'm not kidding you.
Well done.
Thank you.
Watch out for this one.
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to
FoodNetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Fantastic.
All right?
Gino, you're a good man.
GINO: Thank you.
Do they tip?
Sometimes, yeah.
Try this tip --
don't eat yellow snow.
[ Laughter ]
That's the tip for today.