[ Engine rumbling ]
I'm Guy Fieri.
We're rolling out, looking
for America's greatest...
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
[ Cheering ]
♪♪
FIERI: This trip...
[ Clears throat loudly ]
...we're digging
into familiar favorites...
See that fry? Mmm.
...along with some exotic eats.
This is crazy.
Like in a Lansing, Michigan,
joint...
Legit.
...combining sci-fi
with killer pie.
This guy's got it going on.
Plus we've got plates
from Peru in Arizona...
I can't quit shoveling
this in.
...and a pub grub pit stop...
I knew why I liked this.
...bringing the taste of
Philly to North Carolina.
That's a hot pork sandwich
you got there.
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
So I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina.
A lot of people know
this as the Port City
because of the Cape Fear River
and all the history with
the pirates and the Civil War.
And a lot of other folks,
they know it
for all the great beaches
and the vacation spots.
But I'll tell you what
it's gonna get known for --
a funky little joint
that's serving up
simple but real-deal food.
This is The Copper Penny.
♪♪
Drop a crab cake sandwich
and one steak and bacon
sandwich, please.
The food's amazing.
Large buffalo wings.
It's pub food,
but it's inventive.
FIERI: Courtesy of Brian
and Christine Cadwallader,
a husband-and-wife duo
bringing some brotherly love
to this Southern spot.
I heard that you
guys lived in Philly,
then you came back here 'cause
you wanted to be warm again,
and then you thought
you would open up
your own Philly-esque joint.
We needed a place
where my wife could go
and get some good food,
but I could watch the game,
have some wings together.
So you designed your own place
that you wanted to go to.
Absolutely.
FIERI: And while their
signature sandwich
pays homage to their
Philadelphia roots,
it's named for the street
where it's served up.
We got the 109 Chestnut
Chicken Sandwich.
The 109 Chestnut Chicken is
one of my favorites here.
It's got mushrooms
and cheese and chicken.
It's delicious.
We're gonna take some
chicken breast, thin,
a little oil on there.
We're gonna throw
a little dried oregano.
Dried basil, black pepper,
granulated garlic,
and some kosher salt,
and then we're gonna
cook 'em off in the oven.
350 for about 20 minutes or so.
Okay.
As soon as they cool off,
we slice 'em thin on the slicer,
finish 'em on a flat-top.
All right, let's hear about
the famous onion rings.
Oh, these babies are amazing.
Give me the rundown.
Some all purpose flour,
granulated garlic,
black pepper, kosher salt,
and some cayenne pepper
as well.
Got it.
And then we're gonna make
our milk wash for the onions.
Half a gallon of milk,
half a gallon of buttermilk.
Okay.
And my favorite part --
a pint of beer.
Keeping the batter nice
and cold -- great technique.
It's a double dip.
We're gonna go
in the onions, milk wash,
onions, milk wash twice.
"Onions, milk wash,
onions, milk wash twice."
I got it.
So we got some jumbo onions.
Soak 'em in this beer batter
for a second.
Going into our flour mixture,
right back into the milk wash.
Onions, milk wash,
onions, milk wash...
Twice.
Then it goes directly
to a 350-degree fryer
for approximately
three minutes.
[ Mouth full ] Oh, that is
a great onion ring.
All right, we got our chicken,
caramelized onions,
sautéed mushrooms.
-A little provolone?
-Yes, sir.
Steam that for a second.
Toasted bread.
Add our chipotle mayo.
A little Philly cheesesteak
move going right there.
-Yes, sir.
-Huh?
♪♪
The bread is fantastic.
We go to our local baker
every day.
He makes it special for us.
Thin crust, great texture.
Mushrooms, onions --
all ties together.
Very simple, but done
very right and delicious.
[ Crunches ]
Keep those onion rings
away from me.
I never want to see them again.
[ Laughs ]
The onion rings are the bomb.
Big, juicy, tasty.
In terms of a chicken
cheesesteak,
how do you think this does?
I think it stacks up
to the ones in Philly,
for sure.
-Seriously?
-Yeah.
FIERI: And they're making
sure this sandwich
keeps giving
long after it's gone.
MAN: When you buy
the 109 Chestnut Chicken,
they donate $1.09
when you get it on a Tuesday.
[ Mouth full ] So basically,
you take all the profit
from the sandwich
and give it away.
Yeah, we live
in a great community,
so it's our way of giving back.
FIERI: While they're giving
back with the chicken,
they're paying the flavor
forward with the pork.
The hot roast pork sandwich
with hand-cut fries.
Thinly sliced pork
with crispy onions,
and it all just
melts in your mouth.
We're gonna take
a whole pork loin,
add some kosher salt, black
pepper, granulated garlic.
You sear it off, give it
a little caramelization.
Finish in the oven,
350 for about an hour.
Okay.
As soon as she cools,
slice nice and thin.
Next up?
We're gonna make our au jus.
Nice little dipping sauce
for that hot pork sandwich.
That's a hot pork
sandwich you got there!
[ Laughing ]
Throw a little oil
in the pot.
We got our beef trimmed
from all of our steak sandwiches
that we make every day.
Okay.
So you render down all that
beautiful fat and flavor.
Kosher salt, our whole
black peppercorns,
good bunch of garlic cloves,
bay leaves.
Cook that down
for about five minutes.
Okay.
Now we're gonna deglaze that
with a little red wine,
add some mirepoix,
beef drippings.
And then
a bunch of beef stock.
And we're gonna cook that
for probably
two and a half hours.
All right, when this is done,
we strain it?
-Yes, sir.
-Reduce it even a little more?
-And then we're gonna use that
as the jus to dip
the sandwich in?
Yes, sir.
That's a lot of
"Yes, sir, yes, sir."
[ Laughing ]
My mouth's watering.
All right, so now
what are we making?
We are doing our
sautéed spinach.
Got it.
Gonna start us off with
a little olive oil in the pan.
Lots of garlic.
Sauté this down for a second,
drop the spinach.
Crushed red pepper.
I knew why I liked this.
Black pepper.
Very similar to the way I make
sautéed spinach at the house.
Some kosher salt.
Yeah, if that's
a little white wine...
That's it, Chef.
...we eat this spinach
three times a week at my house.
Then we're gonna finish it off
with a little grated parm.
I'd just order
a side of that.
Hand-cut fries.
Cut, soaked, double fried.
-Hot as can be.
-Look at that fry. Mmm!
We got our shaved pork
and some spinach.
Little provolone?
Absolutely.
We got our bread,
roasted garlic aioli.
♪♪
And then we kick it off with
that au jus we just made.
♪♪
Ah-ha-ha.
Man, you can get that
garlic and spinach
in there big time, huh?
Yeah, buddy.
[ Crunches ]
Bread's dynamite,
the pork's not dry.
The spinach has got a ton of
garlic in it, which is perfect.
Don't come in and say,
"I don't want any spinach on it,
just give me a pork sandwich."
So far, spinach is
leading by a bunch.
Bunch of spinach.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
I can. It's my show.
[ Laughing ]
Hand-cut fries,
homemade slaw.
If I lived here, minimum once
a week I'd come in for this.
Oh, I appreciate that.
If you like a Philly
cheesesteak,
you're gonna love that.
That is outstanding.
I appreciate it. Thank you.
The pork is really juicy,
a lot of good flavor.
I'm a huge spinach fan.
It adds a nice little texture.
Sending a basket of onion rings,
bowl of chili.
MAN: I tell anyone that
comes into Wilmington,
go to Copper Penny first thing.
-We're lucky to have 'em.
-You're making it happen.
Real food, a lot of personality.
Very simple, but done right.
-Thank you very much.
-Delicious.
Up next,
in Lansing, Michigan...
[ Chanting ]
[ Laughs ]
...an otherworldly pizzeria...
For people that want to have
a wood-fired pizza experience,
this is it.
...where the surprise is
part of their pies.
And that's where
you just say, "Trust us."
Pork's not dry,
not over seathoned.
Not over seathoned.
A lot of time
the over seathoning...
Absolutely.
...is where you can
really go wrong.
A lot of people don't even know
about over seathoning.
♪♪
I'm here in Lansing, Michigan.
I love coming to areas
like this.
You get all these
old-school buildings
with these really cool
funky joints, like this.
Zoobie's Tavern, but no, no,
that's not where we're going.
We're actually going to
this wood-fired pizza place.
This is The Cosmos.
♪♪
Shrimp going in the window.
It's leaps and bounds above
any other pizza place.
All right, guys,
we have The Trust.
MAN: It's pretty obvious
with the atmosphere
that they're not afraid
to try new things.
FIERI: But what feels new
is actually inspired
by an old pizza parlor
that owner Sam Short
used to visit with his Pops.
Remember they had
the Ms. Pac-Man?
And you could
drink beer there.
You were a kid that
could drink beer?
No, no, no.
My dad would drink beer.
You had a really cool dad.
I would get orange pop
and play Ms. Pac-Man,
and so when I grew up,
I was like,
I want to have
a sci-fi-themed restaurant,
and I want some good pop,
and I want video games,
and I want good beer.
FIERI: And good pie --
scratch-made,
wood-fired,
and topped off right.
Meatball pizza.
You gotta try
the meatball pizza.
The meat is incredible.
The mozzarella is fresh.
What are gonna make?
Our meatballs for our
meatball pizza.
You start off with
some breadcrumbs
and add a little cream.
So we're making
a panade right now.
-You got it.
-So you want your cheese in too?
Yes, please.
Parmesan, and then we go...
-Egg.
-...eggs, pancetta, parsley.
So I guess that was my hint
that I'm supposed to dump it.
Yeah, is that okay?
Well, it's so subtle,
the way you say,
"And then..."
[ Clears throat loudly ]
Garlic.
Diced red onion.
Dried oregano, fennel.
Salt.
And a little black pepper.
We're just straight
ground beef here?
No, we're pork.
We're 50/50.
Are we serving the meatballs
on anything else besides pizza?
We concentrate on pizza,
that's what we do.
Let's not mix it up.
-No tacos.
-No beignets.
-Pizza.
-No lasagna?
-Nope.
-No egg rolls?
-Yeah, no.
Not so much.
Ball 'em up, get 'em done.
At, what,
10 minutes in the oven?
-You got it.
-So you're making mozz.
So where are we at with this?
So, we're at a curd point
right now.
Okay.
So we're gonna go
hot water in the pan.
What we really want to do is
have this start loosening up.
So we're gonna drop
190-degree water in here.
I'm gonna start folding it
over on itself.
-How we looking, we good?
-Yeah.
So we're gonna get our paddle
under the corner.
Got it.
We're gonna get that guy.
[ Whistles ]
Start throwing salt on it.
Right? Here. Here we go.
Yes, sir.
I have seen some interesting
mozzarella methods,
but that might take the cake.
And then we fold, fold, fold.
Look at that, huh?
Yeah.
Meatballs are done.
Mozz is done.
Yeah. Yeah.
Gotta make the sauce.
What's in the sauce?
So we've got crushed
tomatoes, salt,
oregano, granulated garlic.
That's it?
Yep.
Cook it down,
herb blend it,
puree it up, cool it down,
we're ready to rock.
Yeah.
All right, so now we're
ready to put this together.
Start with our dough.
Okay.
Ladle on here.
How many meatballs go on?
Two meatballs on.
And we're gonna start crumbling
them, breaking them down.
Okay.
Fresh mozz diced up
a little bit.
Pickled onions we make in house.
Little peperoncini.
Peperoncini.
And when does
the ricotta come on?
Last thing on here.
Drop it in,
about four minutes.
Right up front.
Yeah.
That's how we roll.
We want to get that
crust nice and hot.
Pull it out and hit it
with a little oil.
♪♪
And serve it up.
Okay.
♪♪
Nice rich tomato sauce flavor,
tender meatball.
♪♪
The acid
from the peperoncini...
Yeah.
...and the pickled red onion
to the contrast of
the sweet ricotta
really comes together great.
Thank you.
♪♪
Great crust. Light, thin,
tight, good chew.
Going the extra step
making the mozz,
brush of the olive oil
at the end.
It's really a great pie.
I really like mozzarella, but
this one's, like, my favorite.
Great smooth tomato sauce,
and then the crust
obviously is to die for.
How do you explain
The Cosmos to people?
When I think Cosmos,
I also think of Zoobie's.
FIERI: That's because
Zoobie's and Cosmos
are part of the same galaxy.
We started
with a bar next door.
-Zoobie's is yours?
-Zoobie's is mine.
Zoobie's...
Was not connected
to this building.
Is it connected now?
Yeah.
Really? How do you get to --
We built bathrooms
between it.
We did it with our hands and
pulled up the carpet ourselves.
'Cause If you did it with your
feet, it would be real weird.
-Yeah, you know.
-You can go to Zoobie's
and pick out your
favorite craft beer
and then head on over here
when you get hungry.
MAN: When they put a little
hallway between
awesome food
and an awesome atmosphere,
it's, like, the best
thing you could do.
And put a restroom
in the middle,
life doesn't get any better.
Right.
What else you got?
Next up, we've got our Trust Us.
Our Trust Us, which means?
You have to trust them
to bring something out
that you're gonna enjoy.
You never know what
you're gonna get,
but it's always good.
Here's the deal.
Come back.
We're hanging out at Cosmos.
We're in Lansing, Michigan.
We're with a big kid.
It's living a childhood dream
and eating great pizza.
See you in a minute.
Want a bite?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, start another one.
Oh, okay.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hanging out
in Lansing, Michigan,
with a gigantic kid.
How tall are you?
6'4".
6'4", and he has
his own pizza joint
and a really cool bar
next door called Zoobie's.
But we're at Cosmos
and we're making pizza.
It's always tasty
and always fresh.
MAN: People are consistently
trying this place
'cause they hear how good it is.
The meatball pizza was legit,
but now you're getting
into a little weird zone
called the Trust Me pizza?
Our Trust Us.
And that's what you
just say, "Trust us."
Trust us, we don't
tell 'em anything.
Do you tell 'em what kind it is?
Mnh-mnh.
MAN: You literally trust them
to make you something awesome,
and they do.
The Trust Us pizza is?
Today is our
duck sausage pizza.
Okay, I'll have that.
So we get our grinder on.
We've got our duck breast
here, skin on.
[ Whirring ]
So here we go.
We've got our duck ground.
Got it.
Now we've got to add
our spices.
Granulated garlic,
cayenne, caraway.
Don't get carried away
with it.
Man!
Crushed pink peppercorn,
sea salt,
ground mustard,
some more of that fennel.
Fun with fennel.
A little onion powder.
And we're gonna
mix it all up.
We're just gonna bake
it all up in a sheet?
You got it.
Okay, in the oven...
and then out.
Yeah, here we go.
What else is on this pizza?
So we've got
a garlic cream sauce.
Start with a little
fresh chopped garlic.
We're just releasing those
aromatics into it, right?
Dig it.
We're adding heavy cream.
Romano cheese,
oven-dried tomatoes,
and then we stir
everything in.
Okay.
So we start by, again,
making our crust.
Cornmeal this guy.
♪♪
So we're gonna add some
of that garlic cream.
We're gonna take some
of this duck sausage.
♪♪
Those oven-dried tomatoes.
So then we're gonna follow
with some ramps,
trumpet mushrooms, and then
we have our mozzarella here,
finally some Taleggio.
-Duck and Taleggio?
-Trust me, man.
-Sounds like a --
-Trust me.
Sounds like a cop movie
out of the '80s.
[ Laughing ]
It's another adventure
of "Duck and Taleggio."
All that together
in the oven with the duck.
All that -- you got it.
Nicely done.
Hot swingin'.
♪♪
[ Exhales sharply ]
Oh, that duck's dynamite.
♪♪
Really nice with
the trumpet mushroom.
Taleggio's perfect.
For people that want to have
a wood-fired pizza
experience, this is it.
All the "Triple D" fans
are gonna come looking for it,
so trust us.
That's right.
Put it on the menu.
You got it.
Good man.
Trust Us with duck
in the window.
They really know
how to complement
each ingredient on the pizza
fantastically.
I've not had a Trust Us
that I didn't like.
Today they delivered again.
Hot pan pie going out.
I've had pizza
in New York and Chicago,
and this holds up as some
of the best I've ever had.
I would say without a doubt
that Cosmos food is
out of this world.
This guy's got it going on.
Watch out, he's dangerous
and very funny.
Right back at you.
Hey, hey,
I resemble that remark.
[ Laughing ]
FIERI: Coming up, we're
headed to Tucson...
That's the bite.
...to grab a first-class
culinary ticket to Peru.
This is not something
you've probably had before.
♪♪
The Andes --
you gotta love it.
"Triple D's"
first visit to Peru.
[ Sighs ]
No, that's not actually true.
I'm actually in Tucson,
Arizona,
but I'm thinking about
Peruvian food,
and I hear there's a local joint
you gotta check out.
This is Inca's.
♪♪
MAN: Lomo saltado.
Inca's is sort of this
hidden diamond in Tucson.
The seco and another ceviche.
It's different. You can't get
this anywhere else in town.
FIERI: And this little slice
of South America
is served up by Fatima Campos,
who isn't actually from Peru,
but was born in Mexico.
Where'd you learn to
cook Peruvian food?
Well, I got in love
with a Peruvian guy.
My mom, she was telling me...
[ speaking Spanish ]
"The love, it starts
from the food."
FIERI: So she found a mentor
in her mother-in-law.
All because you wanted
to impress your new husband?
[ Laughs ]
You went to his mom, learned
all the Peruvian dishes,
and a restaurant was born.
FIERI:
The first dish she tried --
a beef bean and rice plate
that's become one of the
menu's biggest stars.
Seco de carne con frijoles.
Seco de carne is
a delicious beef plate.
Wakes up the taste buds
and zap message to the brain
that says, "Yummy."
♪♪
First we're gonna make
the mix of the fresh cilantro,
water,
and my secret ingredient --
huacatay, the imported herb
from Peru.
Huacatay.
In order for us to import it,
they call it black leaf mint,
but it's different.
It smells like mint.
[ Whirring ]
It's ready.
Let's make the aji sauce.
We just add the chilies.
So the fresh aji, okay.
Imported aji amarillo.
A little bit of water.
What would you say the intensity
of that pepper is?
Jalapeño, serrano?
Ah, worse.
Habanero?
It's very, very spicy.
-Okay, now what happens?
-Now we sear the beef.
-What type of beef?
-Tenderloin.
Everybody in the pool.
Okay, so this is seared now.
We're gonna make a seco paste.
We're gonna add the onions,
the garlic, the cumino.
So all the things that
we love in Mexican food.
Salt, pepper,
and cilantro water.
We're gonna put it all
together,
let it cook for about
an hour and 45 minutes.
This is crazy.
We're gonna finish it up with
the carrots and the peas,
and the aji amarillo.
The puree that we did.
And put in a little bit
of spices.
Got it.
Now the canary beans.
These are from Peru?
Yes.
It's like a navy bean.
How are we gonna make them?
We soak them in the water
for about an hour...
All right.
...and then we let it broil
for almost two hours.
-Which chili is this?
-Aji panca.
Chili Colorado.
Chili Colorado, okay.
[ Laughs ]
We just let it broil for
about two, three minutes.
They came up like this.
Got it.
We're gonna put
a little bit of oil,
sautéed onions and the garlic.
Add the cumino.
Pepper, salt, about a spoon
of the aji panca.
The chili Colorado.
Add a little bit of water.
And then we put
the beans into that?
This into the beans.
Got it, and how much longer
are the beans gonna cook?
For about 25 minutes.
-I'm ready.
-Okay.
Jasmine rice, the beans,
the seco de carne.
Garnish the beans
with onions,
cilantro on top of the rice
just to make it
like Machu Picchu.
[ Laughs ]
I'm dying to try these beans.
♪♪
Boy, those are like butter.
There's a little bit
of spice there.
♪♪
Texturally, the meat's got
a little ropa vieja to it,
but much more tender.
The diversity,
the uniqueness in the dish.
The cilantro sauce -- I mean,
just something like that alone.
And then backed up with
a little bit of heat.
I mean, it's not something
you've probably had before.
I can't quit
shoveling this in.
That bite right there,
where you're getting some
of the pickled onions,
the beans, the rice,
the seco carne --
dynamite.
WOMAN: The meat is savory.
You don't need a knife
to cut it.
The beans are great,
the texture is amazing.
FIERI:
And while the locals love it,
it can be a little
difficult to pinpoint
what makes Peruvian food
Peruvian.
WOMAN: In Tucson, we have
a lot of Mexican food,
and there's some similarities,
but it's also completely
its own flavor.
It's got a lot of spices,
but it's not hot.
It draws from the cultures
and the traditions
from other regions.
FIERI: And this next dish
is a perfect example.
So, lomo saltado over here.
Lomo saltado is -- I mean
that's a staple, right?
It's the signature of Peru.
The key here --
French fries and soy sauce.
It's delicious.
It's fresh, it's flavorful.
Very, very well done.
The key for the lomo
is the beef broth.
-Okay.
-We have the broil water.
Beef trimmings.
Red onions, carrots,
celery, and garlic.
Okay. How long
is this gonna go?
It takes a while.
Okay, and we strain that and mix
the soy sauce with it,
and that's the base sauce
for the lomo saltado.
Exactamente.
That's what makes
the full flavor.
The -- the what?
The full flavor.
[ Laughs ]
This is the beef tenderloin.
Okay.
Salt and pepper, canola oil.
We let it go.
You add the onion.
That is one hot pan.
Yellow chili, and tomato.
Now the sauce.
The beef broth
with the soy sauce.
That's the smell of
lomo saltado that I know.
Yes.
We prepare the rice.
Machu Picchu.
A little bit of the fries.
Any dish that starts off
with French fries, come on.
Lomo saltado beef.
Right over the top.
With a little bit
of cilantro.
Now you can enjoy it.
The key is to get
the French fry
that soaked up that juice,
that beef broth
with the soy sauce.
♪♪
Mmm! That's the bite.
Such a simple dish,
and such a great dish.
What takes it over the top
is when you have that
soy sauce in there.
A little Chinese
community in Peru.
-Really?
-Oh, yes.
Well done.
The meat is super tender,
super flavorful.
The sauce underneath goes
wonderfully with the meat.
Arroz con pollo is ready.
MAN: If you come to Inca's,
you're gonna fall in love
with the food,
and maybe, just maybe,
you'll think you've had
a quick trip to Peru.
Congratulations.
Please visit us at any time,
and we'll make the best
lomo and seco for you.
Adios.
♪♪
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
but don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over this country,
and I'll be looking
for you next time on...
"Triple D"!
[ Cheering ]
Does this have
any cosmic Cosmo name,
or is it just meatball pizza?
It's meatball pizza, man.
-See?
-I know.
Couldn't it be
Spaceballs or something?
I think it has to be.
I think it should --
So the "Triple D"
Spaceball Pizza.
"Triple D" Spaceball Pizza.
Done.
[ Laughing ]