I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're going to round 2
revisiting some of our favorite
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This is Triple D Nation.
♪♪
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
[ Laughing ]
because triple-D joints
have been blowing up.
Did you see that?
And we're going back to see
what's cookin'.
Like on this trip,
a chili parlor in Seattle
that's still not
spilling the beans.
I don't think you have
any intention of telling me.
No, you're right.
A Peruvian joint in Chicago
that's keeping it real.
The beef heart --
Every Peruvian eats this.
Nine years is coming back
like that.
And this guy who spread
an authentic
Thai taste all over Portland.
Everybody's playing
nice-nice.
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors --
that's right here, right now,
on Triple D Nation.
♪♪
So I'm here in Chicago,
one of my favorite cities,
to check out a joint
that I visited nine years ago
almost to the day.
I'd never been to a Peruvian
restaurant before,
and man it started
a list of them after that.
There's only 1 --
this is Taste of Peru.
Tallarines Verdes.
I saw Cesar's restaurant
on Triple D.
I've never had Peruvian food
before I came here.
It's just fantastic.
Ceviche Especial.
Everything okay?
The food was okay?
I like it.
Delicious.
Good, good, good.
There's a lot of variety
and you can try
something different each time
and it can be a completely
different experience.
Una Sopa Viagra.
FIERI: When I first
met owner Cesar Izquierdo
back in 2009,
he was serving huge helpings
of Peruvian classics
his mother taught him.
Coming out in a second.
All from his joint tucked
in the back of a strip mall
next to a laundromat.
This was the big
introduction, man.
Sure:
I've eaten food
from all over the world.
I probably --
one of the foods
I know the least about
is Peruvian food.
The first time Guy
had Peruvian food on Triple D,
we served him the Lomo Saltado.
FIERI: Lomo is this meat?
IZQUIERDO:
Lomo is rib eye.
A little bit of pepper,
salt, garlic.
Creamy, okay --
Yeah, it's great.
Soy sauce last.
Gonna get it ready like this.
We gonna put it
in a frying pan.
Then you flip it.
Now we're gonna add up
the onion.
Throw some tomatoes
go down.
I don't know anybody at home
right now
that's mouth is not watering
'cause mine is.
And the last thing we're waiting
for believe it
or not is french fries.
Come on baby.
We are ready.
♪♪
Mmm.
Mmm, hamburger.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm. Fantastic.
Oh my gosh.
Look at that.
I don't care if you live within
200 miles you should walk here.
Right on point goodness.
I feel that I made a monster
out of him.
That's funny.
Brother, I am telling you
somethin' --
it is simple
and it is off the hook.
I think I'm going to have
to take that sign down,
you know, it's not going to be
"the best kept secret" anymore.
No, it won't.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
[ Telephone rings ]
Were you rolling
on that?
I just want one more bite.
♪♪
Take it away.
[ Laughs ]
We had a great time.
What did we have?
Lomo Saltado and...?
We had Lomo Saltado,
we had the chicken
tamales.
♪♪
That's killer.
And we had the shish kebab.
Welcome back to Triple D.
I'm Guy Fieri and I know
we're all going to be
laughing in a minute
'cause I'm going to be
eating that evidentially.
Oh the heart.
The heart.
The beef heart.
Every Peruvian eats this.
Oh, boy.
With the cow heart shish kebab,
he didn't want to try it.
We're ready.
Mm-hmm.
What I know
is you're going to like it.
I'm gonna like it, huh?
That's right.
It's like filet mignon.
[ Exhales sharply ]
♪♪
No. [ Laughs ]
[ Exhales sharply ]
[ Chuckles ]
Fire!
[ Laughter ]
The taste --
what'd you think?
It's good right?
Mm-hmm.
It's killer.
It's, um...
Like liver?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, it's got
the texture of liver --
a little bit
harder I think.
Yeah, I guess --
Cause someone sold me
on filet mignon --
you know who that guy was?
God, I don't remember.
[ Laughs ]
I can't even believe
I remember that.
Once the show aired --
next day we were flooded.
It was incredible.
Yeah, I had to hire more staff.
I wasn't ready,
but we got it down pat now.
FIERI: Other than updating
your menu to include
that Guy Fieri combo, not much
has changed around here,
and I gotta tell ya, I couldn't
be happier about that.
One of the reasons
I wanted to come back was
because I didn't have a chance
to try the whole menu.
Yeah.
I come in,
I get to try a couple.
I can't eat every dish.
Here's your Ceviche.
All right, so this --
so most of the time
you see Ceviche
and you get
the little pieces.
Uh-huh.
This you do full shrimp.
The Ceviche -- we have the
octopus, calamari, mussels,
clams, scallops, shrimp.
You're gonna mix
all this with lime,
and the salt, the pepper,
and the garlic,
a little bit of celery in there,
and a little bit of rocoto.
It's the Peruvian rocoto
pepper sauce
and condensed milk that
makes this Ceviche Peruvian.
♪♪
The Ceviche is outrageous.
Big shrimp, octopus,
lots of onion in it --
delicious.
And this has been on the menu
the whole time?
Yes.
When I was here
nine years ago?
Yes.
[ Chuckles ]
You was in a hurry --
I'm always in a hurry.
What are you
talking about?
Ceviche is very tasty
and very fresh.
One of the best I've had.
Tried all around the world.
It's just so refreshing.
You get that lime taste
with the Ceviche,
mixed in with all
of the other spices.
It makes the fish pop.
So what else
are we gonna try?
We gonna try
the Arroz con Mariscos.
It's a paella without
the chicken and the sausage.
So this is Peruvian
paella?
Exactly.
With just seafood.
We got green mussels
from New Zealand,
shrimp from the Gulf of Mexico,
we've got Peruvian mussels, too.
We got calamari?
Yes.
We have scallops,
octopus.
I mean, I love paella.
The seafood's really fresh,
the calamari is tender,
the shrimp aren't overcooked,
you get some mussels,
you get some clam,
nice big piece of snow crab,
little saffron in the rice,
some fresh veggies, scallops.
Man, you don't find that.
You don't even find that at
high-end seafood restaurants --
that kind of paella.
Yes.
Well done.
All right,
you got one more?
Yes, sir!
What else?
Tallarines Verdes
con pollo.
Pesto with chicken.
What's the pesto made
out of Cesar?
We mix it with basil
and spinach,
and cheese,
evaporated milk.
Evaporated milk?
That's right.
Yeah, is this traditional
inside of Peru?
That's right.
This is fantastic.
Well done.
Thank you.
MAN:
The chicken pesto is excellent.
The basil, the spinach,
and the grilled chicken on it.
The chicken is super juicy.
The pesto is definitely
different than an Italian pesto.
Cheers to you!
iSalud! iSalud!
To be in this family
of Diners, Drives and Dives,
it meant everything for me.
I mean, you got
some good signage up.
I don't think I've ever seen
anybody promote
their Triple D experience
like you.
It's a gem, and look at all
the people you make happy.
Don't change --
don't change.
I'm so happy to come back
and see that it hasn't changed.
You're still the same way.
You're doing great.
Thank you very much, brother.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
FIERI: And talk about
if it ain't broke don't fix it.
Up next, we're headed
to a dive in Seattle.
You're gonna love it
so much we'll grunt for ya.
From the inside
it's like time stood still.
The only thing
I've seen change here is --
there's a poster
of Guy over there.
FIERI:
But from the outside, that's
a whole different ball game.
So back in 2007,
I'm checking out
this funky joint right outside
Seattle, Washington.
MIKE:
Where's the chili Big Phil?
Come on -- get to work.
Oh, it's a father and son team
that you just gotta meet.
Suck it in big guy.
Now I sent thousands
of friends and families
and Triple D viewers there.
They said, "Oh yeah,
the building's just the same,
but everything
around it has changed."
This is Mike's Chili Parlor.
♪♪
I got four chili dogs
to go coming up.
MAN #1: Mike hasn't changed.
The building looks the same.
A lot of the same faces
that we see in here.
The only thing that I've seen
change here is a --
there's a poster of Guy
over there that he's signed.
That's about it -- everything
else has been the same.
MAN #2:
Mike and his dad are really
the character of this place.
FIERI: Watch out for that guy
right there --
That's Phil.
The normal guy?
That's his son, Mike.
I shouldn't say normal --
the less crazy guy.
Mmm.
Did you just make
an "mmm" grunt for me.
Mm-hmm.
Is that what you did?
Mm, yeah. I'm drooling.
I did it.
I took a bite and you make
an mmm grunt for me.
Yeah.
Wow,
well full-service joint.
You're gonna love it so much,
we'll grunt for ya.
That is great.
Mmm.
[ Laughter ]
One thing you gotta understand
about this place
is that absolutely everything
coming out of that kitchen
is covered in their signature
chili sauce,
which starts with beef stock,
onions, and garlic.
We didn't saute 'em. We just
throw everybody in the pool?
That's right.
Now the meat.
FIERI: What is in this?
Oh, a whole
bunch of stuff.
There's gotta be
some chili powder.
That's what it is.
Oregano.
I don't think you have
any intention of tell me.
No, you're right.
[ Laughs ]
No, absolutely.
No, you're right.
That's all I've never done it
for anybody else.
For anybody else?
Mmm, that's tasty!
Isn't it?
You guys should call this
like a chili parlor.
It'd be a good name.
My favorite part
when Guy was here
really was watching
the interaction
between him and my father.
It was a love affair
from the first bite.
You know what
they just told me?
No.
They said, "We didn't even know
he served chili.
We just come in
for the abuse." [ Laughs ]
That's true.
Mike: Small chili fry
with the works.
Now the big chili fry --
the large chili fry.
No beans
on the chili fries.
Okay.
We already got it started
so we're gonna go
with just the meat.
I'm going medium-wet
because I want to go --
You want it to soak up
a little bit.
I want it to soak up
a little bit while I have
a little extra to dip in.
Right?
On the bottom,
so at the end of the plate.
I dig it.
So there you go.
Mike: I think out french fries
have always been great,
but when Guy was here,
he gave us a tip
to double cook them --
to part cook them and then
cool them and bring them back.
It was just a quick little thing
that he said and the next day
we started doing it
and it was great.
They went from being
kind of cakey almost
to like really being crispy
and golden brown
because you suck the water
out of them now
and then when you drop
them back in the oil
it really fills them up.
They're light, crispy --
they're excellent.
The french fries are amazing,
especially now with --
I think they're twice
cooked or something
so that they're even better.
MAN #3: The fries
are always delicious.
Chili on top and then the cheese
and the onions --
it's just a delicious
combination.
MIKE: This is going to be
a bowl of chili.
Four chili dogs.
FIERI: And besides the fries,
that chili can still be found
on all the staples --
burgers, dogs, pasta --
and watch out --
they'll even try
to put it on ice cream.
Plus, they've inched their way
into some new territory.
MIKE: We don't change very fast
here at Mike's chili parlor
so every 20 or 25 years
we need to add something
to the menu.
Queso coming out.
We've added a chili-queso
that's something
that I would always serve
at parties and things like that.
So I'm gonna toss the onions
in there --
put the garlic in there.
I use sharp cheddar
and medium cheddar together.
It kind of brings up
a little bit of extra flavor.
And I got the little bit
of half-and-half,
just so that's gonna really
add to the creaminess here.
and then we'll add
the good stuff.
FIERI: And the secret
to the queso --
don't even ask --
they don't share
any of their secrets.
Chili-queso is great.
It's cheesy with a little bit
of spice in there.
The cheese kind of helps
with the spiciness of the chili.
It's just delicious on chips --
perfect for watching a game.
We've also added this big chunk
of meat that's called a Meater.
We created this patty
with the onions pressed in it,
and then it just gets
the chili meat sauce
all over the top of it,
and then all the extras on it.
MAN #4: Love the Meater.
It is a big hunk of meat --
a very filling
and satisfying meal.
When you take a bite,
it's full of flavor.
FIERI: Now things might move
at a snail's pace inside,
but outside, that's
a totally different story.
Since Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives was here,
massive development
has happened.
So when they were getting ready
to build this building
next door,
they came and tried
to have a little deal with us.
They walked in all cocky
and said,
"Hey, do I have enough money
to buy you guys out?"
and my dad basically said,
"Beat it."
It's been here
for four generations.
It's really what we do.
It's our family's heartbeat
is this location here.
Triple D has shot
some of the best,
some of the craziest,
some of the funkiest,
but I gotta tell you
when it comes to a family story,
when it comes to a story
about great food,
when it comes to a story about
carrying on your tradition,
I think that
this is pretty amazing.
Now listen,
that is some bomb chili.
Now Mike, why haven't you made
Phil retire yet?
And the other question is why
can't I get mail-order chili?
Spicy wings coming up.
Now coming up,
a joint in Portland...
Awesome dude,
really awesome.
...that you don't have to worry
about mailing you the food
because they've got joints
all over the country.
♪♪
Welcome back to Triple D Nation.
So it's 2009 Portland, Oregon,
at a funky
Thai joint where you walk up
to the window.
Two orders of the Kai Yaang.
SERVER: Cha Ca's in the window.
Here's the Sateh.
Yeah, I think we're going to
start calling the show
Diner's, Drive-Ins
and Walk-Ups.
Coming up with the boar.
Oh the food was outrageous,
so outrageous,
they got five locations --
the Portland, one in New York,
one in Las Vegas,
but ladies and gentleman,
there's only one Pok Pok.
♪♪
Kung Op in nine minutes.
I would say Pok Pok
changed the definition
of what Thai food
is in America.
One Phrai salad coming up.
We saw Guy at Pok Pok
and I'm like,
"Hey there's one that just
opened up in out neighborhood,"
and I've been a regular
there ever since.
MAN #5: I mean, I'd seen
the show a bunch of times.
My wife and I were living
on the East Coast.
We even moved out here.
I tell people Pok Pok's
about 5 to 10 percent
of the reason
that we even moved out here.
Spicy wings coming up.
FIERI: And it's chef
Andy who's dishing out
all kinds of real-deal
Thai that he discovered
while living in Thailand.
And he's going deep
into the cultural cookbook.
Enjoy.
And we don't sell
Pad Thai at all.
Gimme some.
No Pad Thai.
That's what
I'm talkin' about.
You know you're going gangster
when you don't take
the signature item
of the type of food
and put it on your menu.
Aw, that's legit dude.
We're making Muu Paa Kham Waan,
which is boar collar.
We did the boar collar,
with a really spicy sauce
and iced mustard greens.
Northern Thai
drinking food.
Looks good, huh,
hungry camera?
Nope.
[ Laughs ]
Not today.
We also did Som Tam
or Papaya Pok Pok.
Start out with a little bit
of garlic, a couple of chilies.
You like it spicy?
I'll take it spicy.
Then we'll make it
three chilies,
nice big scoop
of palm sugar --
then I'm gonna start
pounding that down.
That's Pok Pok.
Next will be fresh limes
with the skin and juice.
Garlic-lime-chili
mojito going.
That's pretty much it.
Fried shrimp, then you're going
to follow that
with some long beans.
And now the green papaya.
This is all grated
fresh each time?
Grated fresh.
We're gonna start pounding it
all together here.
The dressing gets kind of pushed
into the green papaya,
but the green papaya
stays nice and crunchy.
And each time
this is the routine?
This is the way
we do it every time.
Man, someone's gotta be
working hard at this job.
And then we pound each salad
to order and Guy
was really impressed
that we were making it fresh
like that every single time,
and we still do to this day.
Then you gotta eat this
with sticky rice.
My hope was that he was going to
like it as much as I did,
and luckily he did.
Mmm, wow.
You get all the flavors,
the crunch, the presentation,
everybody's playing nice-nice.
There's no lead guitar in this.
Awesome dude --
really awesome.
FIERI:
But the buzz on the street
was about the wings.
And there, I had heard
about those wings.
If I hear one more person
come and tell me,
"Hey you that Dude from Diner's,
go get the spicy chicken."
Why even have
anything else?
You should just have
chicken wings.
Yeah, you know
I've thought about it.
I've thought about
just gutting the shack
and putting some fryers in there
and just making wings.
RICKER:
I think guy was skeptical
because we were using just a --
kind of a dredge
for the wings --
no batter or anything
like that -- no wash.
I'm not typically a fan
of a dredged wing,
but since it's such
a fine flour,
I'll try it.
RICKER:
You want it spicy?
Ah, throw a little
heat on it.
Some of this
chili paste here.
That's going to give it
that nice, toasty spice flavor.
We're going to pull
those wings out.
They get tossed
right in there.
Then we're going to throw
in our fried garlic.
Wow, you can see that candy
right on there.
Then we're just going to do
a little trick here --
fish sauce oil with just
a touch of water.
We'll just chuck it off
the side of the pan,
then we'll let those cool
a little bit.
I think we won him over.
Mmm. That sauce on
the outside of that
with that tempura flour
makes it.
What a dish.
How many of these have you
put away in your lifetime?
Probably more than
you've had hot meals.
[ Laughs ]
So when Guy left he said
be plenty aware
that the dishes
that you showed us today
are likely gonna be the things
you're going to sell
the most of going forward.
Well Guy's prophecy
came true.
FIERI: Boy did it ever.
Now we sell chicken wings
more than any other dish.
Some Vietnamese wings
for you.
FIERI: Check out how this place
has totally blown up the bird
when we come back.
♪♪
Welcome back to Triple D Nation.
I'm here in Portland, Oregon
[laughs]
and I'm checking out this joint,
it's called Pok Pok.
So Pok Pok is this tiny little
place with a walk-up window.
We opened up in 2005
as just this shack right here,
and basically we've been
Frankensteining
onto it since then.
Can you give me your best
Frankenstein impression.
[ Groaning ]
Sat down -- ate the food.
Try it?
I was blown away.
Mmm.
What a dish.
And those Vietnamese wings
were out of bounds.
Now we sell chicken wings
more than any other dish.
Vietnamese fish sauce wings
for you.
RICKER: We process about
6,000 pounds of chicken wings
a week these days.
Not only did everybody who
came have to order the wings,
at this point they've
even opened a spin-off
that's just Pok Pok
Wing because they're so popular.
RICKER: We really feel fortunate
to have been on the show
because we established a dish
that has become iconic,
and what that allows us to do
is to offer some more
of the esoteric dishes
that I really love
about the cuisine,
like the Tam Khanun.
This dish is called Tam Khanun,
that means "pounded jackfruit."
There's not
a whole lot of flavor,
but it carries other flavors
really well--
FIERI: Like the rendered
pork fat
and Thai curry base
that it's fried in.
When you fry it with all
these different aromatics
it makes a really
delicious dish.
There's ground pork,
pork cracklings,
a little bit of tomato,
it's super good.
The jackfruit is really meaty.
MAN #6: I didn't even know
what jackfruit was --
one of the most
delicious things
that I've probably
ever had here.
The last time
Triple D visited here
this was more or less
an open-air lean-to
where we had our charcoal fires
and our grills kind of outside.
What do you do when it rains
heavy out here?
Get wet?
We just get wet.
It's Oregon man.
Now we have this really nice
kitchen and everything --
it's totally enclosed --
much more luxurious.
Also I was able to introduce
a new menu of food.
Kung Op in nine minutes.
FIERI: Like Kung Op Wun Sen,
better known as prawns
with glass noodles.
This is a dish of Chinese origin
and there's a whole
tradition there of baking
in clay pots over charcoal.
You're going to line
the bottom of the pot
with sliced pork belly,
vegetables on top of that,
whole head-on prawns,
and then the glass noodles,
Chinese celery on top,
then we add a Kung Op Wun Sen
sauce that we make in-house.
FIERI: That's a sweet combo
with hints of oyster sauce
and Chinese red wine.
Set it on top of the charcoal
and in about nine minutes
from now
it should be ready to go.
MAN #5: It's just so special
when they open up the cover
to the clay pot
and you get the aroma.
Oh, my god.
It smells so good.
MAN #5: There's pork belly,
the shrimp are
really perfectly cooked inside,
and the sauce
is just incredible.
Kung Op in the window.
FIERI: Now Andy's
got five restaurants
dishing up these Thai treats.
And there's no sign of this guy
slowing down.
Since you guys last visited,
I've gotten
about ten years older
and I spend a lot more time
in Thailand now.
Kung Op's nine minutes out,
I'm gonna go ahead
and make the papaya salad.
It's always busy.
And it never disappoints.
It's just really an experience.
Guy, I've got
to tell you something.
I've still had more wings
than you've had hot meals.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So there you have it
on Triple D.
We're going coast-to-coast
from Chicago, to Portland.
I mean, we've got Peruvian,
we've got all-American,
and we've got Thai.
Delicious food
by crazy people --
a joint you'll never forget --
all 'cause of you
and Triple D Nation.
I'd like to thank the cow
that this came from,
and the guy
that picked the bean,
and, I'd also like to thank
the magic bag
that had the spices in it.
[ Laughter ]