I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh...
...we're traveling
the nation...
Huh?
What do you think of that?
...for an international
flavor fest.
This will change
your life.
Like a real-deal
street-food spot...
Everything
is just done right.
...crushing it Thai-style
in Dallas.
You just wreck it for everybody.
You know that, Jack?
Plus an out-of-the-box joint
in Miami.
That's like half of
an empanada planet.
Not playing by the rules
with Venezuelan.
This is crazy.
And an Ethiopian abode
in Tucson...
Wonderful place.
...dishing out
an unforgettable experience.
This is completely
lights out.
[ Claps ]
Thank you.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
[ Engines revving ]
So I'm here at Tucson, Arizona.
It's kind of like
a cultural melting pot.
So many people coming here,
bringing all these
different ethnicities.
So I'm not surprised to find out
they've got a real-deal
Ethiopian restaurant
that's been rocking it
for over 24 years.
This is Zemam's.
♪♪
Sampler is ready.
The flavors are different
than anything I've had.
It's really fresh,
it's really authentic.
FIERI: That's because
at the heart
of this family-run joint
is Amanuel Gebremariam,
who's originally from
the country of Eritrea,
which borders Ethiopia.
Dad, can you hand
me a little plate?
And he's bringing the flavors
and traditions of East Africa
straight to Arizona.
If people that don't
understand Ethiopian food,
how do we describe it?
You eat commune way, you
don't eat individual plates.
You don't get only
one single dish.
You get at least three
or four different varieties.
And it's all getting
done in the house
where Amanuel once lived
with his wife and kids.
And the name?
It's named after my mom.
-"Zamam's."
-Yes.
-Right.
-For all the moms.
For all the moms.
I named it after Za'mams.
-Yeah.
So what are
we gonna make today?
The bread called injera.
The injera is kind of
like a tortilla, almost.
And you peel pieces off
and scoop the food up with it.
We are going to mix
the flour into the water.
This is the leftover dough
we use as a starter.
Okay.
And we start mixing
it with our hand.
The oldest kitchen
equipment known to man.
It takes about 24
hours to ferment.
Okay, Guy.
You pour some.
♪♪
That's it.
Your turn now.
Huh, what do you
think of that?
Not bad, huh?
-Yeah.
I can't color
inside of the lines,
but, boy, I can pour
on some batter.
Whoa. Next,
what are we gonna make?
Gomen Alicha.
-Ah gone a lit ya.
-Yes.
Yes, Gomen Alicha.
It's a vegetable dish.
Lots of turmeric in it.
So it's robust.
-The cabbage keeps it crunchy,
then you have the softer, more
cooked carrots and potatoes.
We pour this cabbage
into the pan,
pour some water
to boil it.
So cabbage and water.
And then we make
the sauce separate.
Onions.
And then what we do is...
We have an album coming
out next Thursday.
We add the oil,
the tomato sauce,
turmeric, potatoes,
the carrots.
And rosemary
and garlic.
So when that's cooked and
the cabbage is cooked,
we're gonna mix
it all together.
Yes.
This is
the finished product.
This is the chickpea
that comes on the side,
and now there is
the beans and carrots.
Lots of carrots in
Ethiopian food, huh?
That's why
we have bright eyes.
Bright eyes.
Collard green,
you will love this.
And here is
the red lentils.
Gorgeous.
Tear a small piece.
You grab it
from the top.
And that's what you do.
That is fantastic.
It's got a little acid to it.
The injera is really
one of the best parts
of this whole thing.
It's nice and light,
and these little holes
really add this
little texture piece.
I've never had Ethiopian
food like this.
The way
you balance the flavors.
This is completely
lights out.
[ Claps ]
-Thank you.
What happened?
[ Both laugh ]
Gomen Alicha, ready.
MAN: The cabbage dish
is really unique.
It's so subtle,
and then all of a sudden,
it just explodes.
We have eight dishes
to make right now.
MAN #2: Amanuel's a great guy.
He's brought all this
unique food to Tucson,
so we're lucky to have him.
I came here to this beautiful
country as a refugee.
I didn't speak English.
I don't know if I speak
English very well right now.
You're doing fantastic.
-Hey, guys.
-Hi, Amanuel.
He's been through a lot.
It's amazing, his resilience.
We got more?
We are going to
make Yedoro Watt.
The Yedoro Watt
is a chicken dish.
It's a little bit spicy.
We are doing
the berbere sauce.
And berbere is
the traditional spice
that's used
in a lot of dishes.
Exactly, that's what makes
Ethiopian dishes hot.
Cayenne pepper.
That's hot.
Paprika, ground coriander,
the garlic, fenugreek.
I'm a friend of Greeks.
Ginger, oil,
some water.
This is the paste.
Okay.
We have to clean
the chicken,
really take all the fat out.
Why?
Traditionally, we don't
eat the greasy or fat food.
That's why
you look like that,
and that's why I look
like this, thanks a lot.
Onions,
the tomato sauce, oil,
berbere that we mixed,
the garlic.
We put the clean
chicken into the pan.
So how long is this
gonna cook, chef?
About an hour
and a half.
Now we are ready to
serve the Doro Watt.
Are you gonna close
the door, or what?
[ Laughing ]
Here's the chicken.
The split pea,
the green split.
Are we doing this
again?
-Yes, sir.
-Oh, I'm gonna die.
The lamb, spinach,
non-spicy beef.
♪♪
That is some of the best,
good, clean chicken
I've ever had.
If chili had a chicken cousin,
it would be right there.
The lamb's fantastic.
Spinach is dynamite.
Each one of the dishes
is individually
its own little song.
And what comes together
is the Ethiopian musical.
SERVER:
Here's your Yedoro Watt.
It just jumps right off your
tongue, every bit of it.
All the way through
is delicious.
WOMAN: It's a perfect
family restaurant.
You're all sitting
around a table.
You're all picking
a different food.
It's fun to eat
with your hands
and not have it
be rude, yeah.
Your mouth just always
has a treat waiting.
The greatest thing
that I get in my travels
of "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives"
is to meet people like you
and to taste the story.
The food is fantastic.
But there's something
about you and your story,
this little house,
that makes it taste
even more incredible.
I appreciate that,
thank you.
FIERI: Up next, a passport
to Thailand in Texas...
You're offering something
great to people.
...where the cooking is killer.
I would eat this
by the truckload.
...and the chef is
too legit to quit.
Get it, Jack.
This from the piece
you've got.
Put on the headband,
yes, no?
There's no headband?
♪♪
If you've been watching "Triple
D" for any period of time,
you know I love ethnic food.
And not just the food,
the people.
Not just the people,
their stories.
So I'm here in the Uptown
neighborhood of Dallas, Texas,
where an immigrant
from Thailand is
living the American
dream and crushing it
in so many ways.
Welcome to CrushCraft.
Drunken noodle out.
Very similar to what you get
in Thailand on the streets.
WOMAN: Your papaya salad.
My mouth waters every
time I walk in the door.
WOMAN #2:
You really feel like
you stepped out of Dallas
and into
somewhere different.
This is the real deal.
FIERI: 'Cause owner
Jack Nuchkasem's menu
is full of the flavors he loved
growing up near Bangkok.
Every time that I eat
a burger, I'm sorry,
I love the burger,
but I keep thinking
about my Thai food.
So he opened up this place
built on classic Thai dishes,
inspired by his mom's cooking.
And why CrushCraft?
Everything we do in Thailand
in the Thai kitchen,
you have to smash it
and crush it.
Making the paste,
making the curry.
And basically, it
became every time
when they like the food,
they said, "You crush it."
Oh...
And they're staying true
to form with this dish.
Here's your green curry.
They make the curry
with the real spices.
It's just like exactly that
I have in Thailand.
Alright, chef, let's do it,
let's get into this.
We're gonna make
green curry paste.
-Okay.
-Golden curry.
Golden curry.
Lemongrass.
-Lemongrass.
-Garlic.
-Garlic, shallots, yes.
Shrimp paste.
-Shrimp paste is key.
The zest
of the Sri Lanka lime.
Cilantro stem
and chili pepper.
-Coriander.
The Sri Lanka lime
leaves themselves.
Thai basil,
salt, vegetable oil.
And you're gonna have
to use that wand,
because there's not a
lot of liquid in there,
so you start breaking
those veggies down.
-You're right.
-Next, we cook it up.
With the oil
and the paste.
[ Whistles ]
A little bit of the
coconut milk in there.
Cook it about
probably 30 seconds,
and then we put the rest of
the coconut milk in there.
Creamy.
The chicken breast.
Not browning it
or anything.
Just dropping it
right in.
We need to add a little
bit of water in there.
Sugar, chicken base,
Thai chili pepper.
What do we have
there, shrimp paste?
Shrimp paste.
-Green beans.
-Bamboo shoot.
Sri Lanka lime leaves.
The eggplant,
the Thai basil.
That's altogether
just for one dish.
Let it sit for maybe
two to three minutes.
Two to three minutes.
-And then we'll get the rice.
-You get the rice.
I'm sorry.
♪♪
Don't be shy, Thai guy.
Here we go.
Dude.
You just wreck it
for everybody.
You know that, Jack?
-[ Laughs ]
-It's not fair.
The depth of that curry.
There's just enough heat
that it starts
to sting a bit,
but then it mellows out.
I get a little bit
of that shrimp paste,
of the Thai chili.
Right.
You get ginger,
you get garlic.
♪♪
That's one of the best
curries I've ever had.
Thank you.
We call that in
Dallas, crush it.
Yeah, we kind of
call that around
the rest
of the country, too.
Green curry,
table number three.
The chicken
is moist and tender.
I absolutely love it.
Complete.
You feel like this is
an authentic experience.
FIERI:
And it's not just the food.
Jack's got the
whole place jammin',
like a Bangkok bazaar.
This restaurant
definitely makes you
feel like I'm in Thailand.
It kind of feels like
you're in a market.
There's always
a good buzz in here.
Alright, what are
we gonna make next?
Wait, don't tell me.
You think about it.
So here's the deal.
We're hanging out at
CrushCraft in Dallas, Texas.
When we come back,
Jack the man is gonna
make us another
great dish.
After I go to sleep.
-Alright.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We are in Dallas, Texas,
hanging out with Jack the chef.
Believe it or not,
the guy's from Thailand.
I still
don't believe that.
I think that accent is,
like, Northwest Dallas.
[ Laughs ]
Egg going on right now.
Whenever I get a Thai craving,
this is my go-to spot.
I gotta be honest
with you,
the green Thai curry
that I just had,
almost food coma,
but he says to come back
because he's got something
fantastic to make.
And we're gonna
have a papaya salad.
-Green papaya?
-Green papaya.
[ Inhales sharply ]
That's one of my favorites.
I've never had anything
so good,
and I get it every
time I come here.
If you have never had
green papaya salad,
do me a favor.
Try to come down to
CrushCraft, but if you can't,
go find any Thai restaurant
that has it, and enjoy it.
Let me see it, brother.
-We peel it first.
-Get all the green off.
-Just going around.
I like to do this.
Nice and thin.
Now we're gonna
make a papaya salad.
Garlic.
-Okay.
We're gonna have
to smash that.
It's like the culinary
version of Whack-A-Mole.
Thai chili.
Green beans
gonna get muddled?
Yes.
Fresh papaya in there.
Palm sugar
and fish sauce.
-Palm sugar and fish sauce.
-Fresh lime juice.
Then you smash it.
Tomato.
Okay. And crushed,
roasted peanuts?
Put it in a bowl
right here.
Okay.
♪♪
I would eat this
by the truckload.
The sugar, the fish sauce,
the lime juice,
the Thai chili,
the garlic.
All muddled together
with that fantastic
texture of the green papaya
that just soaks it up.
It's like the best cold
noodle salad you've ever had.
This will
change your life.
Don't you think?
-Yes, sir.
-Time for drunken noodle.
-Let's do it, buddy.
-Yeah.
The drunken noodle is
my favorite dish here.
WOMAN #3:
All the freshness of the smell,
that's what you smell on
the streets of Thailand.
Drunken noodle sauce.
Vinegar, sugar,
sweet soy sauce.
-Okay.
-It's a seasoning soy sauce.
Lot of different types
of soy sauce, by the way.
-Oyster sauce.
-Oyster sauce, okay.
Next step.
We're gonna start making
marinated chicken.
You add a little bit of oil
in there,
chicken base, sugar,
and oyster sauce.
And what in the world
is gonna happen
with this
evaporated milk?
It's gonna help
tenderize the chicken.
Let it sit
a couple hours.
Let's fire it up, buddy.
A little oil in there.
The chicken, make sure
it's fully cooked.
-Okay.
-Yeah, here we go.
Then we put
a little oil in there.
Some Thai chilies
and some garlic.
Thai chili and
some garlic, yeah.
And chicken, onion,
bell pepper,
tomatoes, basil.
Then we put the sauces
that we just made.
Now the big, fat noodles?
-Right.
Get it, Jack.
That's like a ballet
in Flavor Town.
Drunken noodles.
I saw everything that
you put in here, Jack.
Yet, the flavors
still allude me.
The chicken is really
nice and tender.
The veggies are crisp.
Everything
is just done right.
It's the balance.
I'm so glad
I don't live by you,
'cause this would be
a place I would be at
at least
five times a day.
SERVER: Drunken noodles.
My favorite part about
the drunken noodles
is the fact that it
is a little spicy.
Fresh wok-seared taste.
Little "Triple D" O.G.,
Justin and Diane
from Pecan Lodge.
Does CrushCraft
stand up?
It's an awesome spot.
Atmosphere's great,
the food is amazing.
We eat a lot of Thai food,
and this is the best
I've ever had.
NUCHKASEM: Kra Pao,
table number five.
You're offering something
great to people.
One of my favorite
things now
to come back to Dallas is
gonna be come and see you.
'Cause the food is legit.
You are the real deal.
-Thank you, sir.
-Nice to meet you.
FIERI: Coming up in Miami...
That thing's
out of bounds.
...an empanada emporium...
That is like
a righteous empanada.
...getting downright
funky with the flavor.
This is the Venezuelan
Monte Cristo.
♪♪
So when I see
the Miami food scene,
I realize this is
like a melting pot
of all these great
Latin flavors.
And one of my favorites
is Venezuelan.
So I'm here to check out a joint
where a family is
rocking the empanadas.
This is Milly's
Empanada Factory.
Pork arepa for Michelle.
The best Venezuelan food
that you're gonna find
is gonna be here.
SERVER: Beef patacon.
WOMAN: You take a bite,
and you think of home.
You think of somebody's
mama in there cooking,
and she is.
FIERI: That's right.
Milly Martinez has
been serving up
Venezuelan food in South Florida
for more than two decades.
Your mom is like
an empanada goddess.
Yeah, she is.
And she's passed on
her know-how
to daughter Maria
and son José.
What makes
a great empanada?
A great empanada is
crunchy on the outside,
a little bit sweet,
savory in the inside.
And always piping hot.
Here are your
chicken empanadas.
You come to Milly's and you
have to have an empanada.
One of the best in the world.
We just go from total,
typical empanada kitchen
to, like, factory room.
It's a factory room, and
everything's built to our size,
as you can see.
Yeah, you guys have
done that right.
Yeah, we're gonna make our
dough for our empanadas.
We're gonna start
off with some water.
White corn meal.
Yellow corn meal.
This gives a little
bit of sweetness.
Some sugar.
Some salt and some oil.
So no leavening agent.
Nope, the dough is gonna be
very thin and very crispy.
Okay.
Mix it for five minutes.
Next.
ATENCIO: Chicken breast
in salt
for our chicken empanada.
Chicken breast in salt.
So it's gonna cook down
in its own liquids
for an hour
and 45 minutes.
Chicken breast in salt.
We're gonna let
the chicken cool down,
shred it, and then all
the flavoring comes
when we make our sofrito.
I'm gonna start with some
oil, some diced onions,
diced red peppers.
Got it.
Green peppers,
the diced green onions.
Is this
the type of sofrito
your mom made when
you were a kid?
Absolutely, and it
hasn't changed at all.
Bunch of garlic,
cilantro, some mint.
-Oregano?
-Some salt.
And some annatto oil.
Yeah.
You're gonna get some really
beautiful saffron color.
This is all gonna
get translucent?
After about 20 minutes
or so.
That's gonna get folded
into the shredded chicken.
Correct,
let's spoon this in.
Got it.
Chicken broth,
annatto oil.
Fold it in.
Next thing we're gonna do is
make this actual empanada.
Yeah.
Grab a portion of our chicken
filling, fold it over.
We're gonna cut this out.
Dude,
that's not an empanada.
That's like half of
an empanada planet.
So we're gonna drop that
in the fryer, 350 degrees?
Yes,
our empanadas are ready.
That's a lot of empanada.
And we have a parsley
sauce that goes with it.
Parsley sauce.
Water, onions, parsley,
green peppers,
garlic, salt,
sugar,
a little bit of vinegar.
Put this on.
Now we're gonna add
this parsley mix
into the bowl
of mayonnaise.
Parsley sauce.
Don't think
I've ever had that.
♪♪
I gotta be honest.
I've had some really
good empanadas,
but that's
a gangster empanada.
[ Laughs ]
The sauce is great.
Oh, the sofrito,
it's got it going on.
The interesting thing is,
which I was hating
on the fact that
you were using
the chicken breast
in the pressure cooker,
but you want that
texture and the chew
that you get
from the chicken.
Otherwise, the
chicken will be just
a little too soft
and flabby.
Does got a little bit of
sweet little kiss to it,
totally crunchy,
tender on the inside.
That is, like,
a righteous empanada.
Okay, Michelle.
Empanada's for you.
It's a delicious
flavor explosion.
FIERI: And while they've got
classic Venezuelan locked down,
they're not afraid to
get a little creative.
One Pabe-Yoyo.
Is there really a dish in
Venezuela called Pabe-Yoyo?
There is not.
We got two traditional
Venezuelan plates
and put them together.
-Okay.
FIERI: And they're taking
beef and beans
from a lunch plate
called the pabellon
and putting it inside a
plantain sandwich called a yoyo.
We're gonna make
our shredded beef.
Pressure cooker,
skirt steak, and salt.
-Yes.
-How many hours?
About an hour and
and 45 minutes.
We're gonna shred it, and
then mix it with sofrito
for our Pabe-Yoyo.
Now into the black beans.
You've picked through
these, I take it.
Yes, we have.
We're gonna put these
dried beans, water,
salt, diced-up garlic,
cumin, green peppers,
cilantro, green onions,
and some bay leaves.
-How long is this gonna go?
-One hour.
It's time for our very
ripe sweet plantain.
FIERI: Which winds up becoming
like bread for the sandwich.
Now we're gonna make
some batter
that we're gonna dip
these plantains in.
You look sad,
what's the batter?
Water, salt.
Sugar.
Mm-hmm, baking soda,
and egg yolk.
That's got some flour
in there.
Yeah, that's like
pancake batter.
Oh, yeah.
Alright,
plantains are done?
Yeah, we're gonna
press them down.
Now we have
some queso blanco.
-Okay.
-Some ham.
Top it off
with another slice.
We like our plantains.
Dip it in our batter
that we just made.
-And then fry it?
-And then put it in the fryer.
So this is the
Venezuelan Monte Cristo.
Yes.
First part of our dish.
Alright,
the yoyo is ready.
We're gonna
slice this open.
And now we're gonna introduce
the pabellon into it.
Okay.
Start off
with the black beans,
and then our carne machada.
-Carne machada.
-Shredded queso blanco.
Okay.
And then our parsley
sauce goes right on top.
This is crazy.
Dude, this weighs,
like, a pound.
[ Laughs ]
It really does.
The insane concoction
that I'm eating right now
doesn't exist in Venezuela.
No.
It's hot, it's sweet,
it's salty, it's cheesy.
♪♪
It's creamy, it's fried.
That thing's
out of bounds.
Thank you.
Here we have
a Pabe-Yoyo for you.
It's so savory,
it's so sweet.
It's great that they
actually give you the foil,
'cause if not, it's
gonna fall all over you.
So here's one of my
favorite chefs in Miami.
Actually just one of my
favorite chefs in general.
You've seen him on "Triple D,"
you've seen him on "Triple G."
Chef Richard,
what do you think?
They took the time
to flavor the meat.
The sweet plantain inside.
Then you have this
beautiful, crispy crust.
It's great.
Mandongas for Joseph.
This place is really special.
I haven't been able to
find anything like it.
The prices are good,
the family's great.
Well done, brother, well done.
-Thank you so much.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more
joints all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Divers, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
[ Telephone rings ]
Thanks for calling
CrushCraft.
This is Guy.
Can I help you?
Yes, 17 spring rolls
and a pepperoni pizza?
Got you,
thanks for calling.
Pepperoni pizza.
[ Laughs ]
It was for me.