Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh!
...we're playing a game
of off-the-chain chicken.
Oh, that works.
We've got Nashville Hot
near Oakland...
You got me
at hello, Chef.
...a French twist in Seattle...
Voilà!
...and a hearty taste
of the South...
It's elevated
comfort food.
...mixed in
with some island fever.
[ Both laugh ]
I have seen it all.
[ Meza laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, here I am on
the big island of Hawaii
in Kona on Ali'i Drive,
and this is where
you'll find the restaurants.
But you never know
what's on the second floor.
That's why you got me
and "Triple D."
We're here to check out a joint
that's got island flair
with some Southern attitude.
This is Foster's Kitchen.
WOMAN #1: Flatbread's up!
It's just a really fresh take
on comfort food.
Gumbo and garlic bread
in the window.
It's got a lot
of local style to it,
but it's really
some down-home great food.
FIERI: What he's trying to say
is that owner, Jeff Foster,
is stamping his native spin
on the local goods.
We're from the South.
Lived here a long time, though,
and wanted to kind of mix
a little Pacific Rim cuisine
with some Southern flair.
Which means
that Chef Sheldon Meza
is the perfect fit.
Order up in the window.
He grew up in North Carolina,
but has also jumped right into
the Rainbow State's rhythm.
Purple your color?
Is it purple?
What is it?
It's fuchsia.
[ Laughs ]
Let me get that right.
Fuchsia.
Every day's
a different color.
Is there now?
But everything matches,
from the shoes to the hat.
I have got it
going right here.
[ Laughs ]
I like looking good
while I'm making good food.
Stuffed chicken, red-eye gravy.
Order up.
Southern stuffed chicken.
It's crispy, juicy, cheesy.
It has prosciutto
and Hamakua red-eye gravy.
You can't beat it.
So we're gonna make
our stuffed chicken breasts.
Okay.
Butterfly this.
Salt and pepper on there.
Pound this out a little bit.
Make sure it cooks even.
Put my cheese,
which is Irish cheddar,
mozzarella,
and Parmesan,
inside of the prosciutto.
Can I just have the cheese
and the prosciutto?
[ Laughs ]
You could have whatever
you want, boss.
Little flour dredge,
glue it together,
and it gives you
a nice, little crust.
You'll sear both sides,
finish it in the oven.
We'll make the gravy?
Red-eye. Mm.
Don't start me
on red-eye gravy!
We got our rib eye.
We basically
cook that in the oven
to get all
the fat drippings off
so we can make
a roux out of it
and mix it with butter.
-Okay.
Add our flour,
mix it together.
Now we're making the stock.
Little bit of oil just
to get these babies sauteing.
So this is all your peels,
all your trims.
Garlic, thyme,
bay leaf, peppercorn.
That'll be our band.
We're Bay Leaf
and Peppercorn.
[ Laughs ]
Cooked rib eye, water,
salt, pepper, onion powder.
Garlic powder.
Let this sit here
and steep.
About eight hours.
And that's all just
the base for the gravy.
Got our brewed Kona coffee.
Then we're gonna add
our roux.
Let's put this
together, man.
Homemade mashed potatoes.
We got broccolini,
zucchini, and carrots.
We got our stuffed chicken
out the oven.
Okay.
Our gravy
that we made earlier.
A grilled Maui onion.
Sauteed Hamakua mushrooms.
Little bit of herb oil
for color.
Purple orchids
grown on the island.
Just finish it with
a little bit of razzle-dazzle.
Mm.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
The Kona red-eye gravy
is perfect.
It gives enough bite,
enough attitude,
enough enthusiasm
that it changes it
and doesn't...
let it stay boring.
You took a really
nice Southern dish,
inspired it with
that Irish cheddar.
You got
some good tang in there.
And the mushrooms carry it
all the way through.
It's elevated
comfort food.
[ Laughs ]
Nice job, Chef.
Thank you.
-Stuffed chicken.
-It's so tender,
WOMAN #2:
and when you cut into it,
the prosciutto's in there,
and the cheese
is just coming out.
It's my favorite dish.
Chef Sheldon is amazing.
He's that combination
of Southern hospitality
and the local 'ohana.
How'd you
get out here?
Honestly,
after culinary school,
came to Hawaii,
found out about poké,
and instantly fell in love.
Just didn't want to leave.
Your citrus avocado poké.
MAN #1: Citrus avocado poké
is delicious.
It's fresh. It's got
the Hawaiian flair to it.
So we're making poké.
Poké.
Bringing in
the fresh tuna.
Just gonna cut this
into cubes.
Yes, sir.
This is gonna be with
avocado and what?
So, it's gonna have
avocado mousse.
So a little salt,
a little lime juice.
Exactly,
so I'm gonna pulse this.
Basically, just incorporating
air, making it real light.
This is just
your own spin on it,
'cause most people
just throw the cubes --
The chunks.
Yeah.
Yes.
So now we've got
our pico de gallo.
Okay.
Diced pineapple.
Fresh.
Some creamed oranges,
red onion,
cilantro, jalapeño.
Some salt,
some lime juice.
We're gonna move on to
our spicy black-bean glaze.
Some minced garlic,
habanero pepper.
Some crushed
red chili flakes.
Sweet chili sauce.
That's like
the condiment of the island.
Black bean
garlic sauce.
Blend this all up.
Have our brown sugar.
Balance the sweetness
with the heat.
Orange juice, white vinegar.
Sesame oil.
Can we please put this dish
together now? You're killing me.
[ Laughs ]
This is like culinary purgatory
you've got me in.
Oh, that works.
I'd serve that on a flip-flop.
[ Laughs ]
Beach, flip-flop --
get it?
Let's build this thing.
Wontons and cabbage.
We got our poké
we cut earlier.
Little bit
of the sauce.
Sesame oil with a little bit
of that habanero.
Yes.
Avocado mousse.
Don't mousse it up.
[mess]
Salsa, and then
sesame citrus oil.
It's citrus juice,
sesame oil, salt,
and a little bit of sugar.
-Okay.
We got our black-bean glaze.
The micro cilantro.
Finish with sesame seeds.
So, all this
Southern influence,
and then you go crazy
with this
Polynesian island poké.
[ Laughs ]
Your balance
is fantastic.
The thing that I like
most out of it,
besides the fact
that the ahi is phenomenal,
is that black-bean puree.
You got a nice little tang,
a little funk.
And the mousse. I love to get
the avocado in there,
and not just have it
that big avocado note.
It's silky.
You're crushing this, dude.
That poké
is no joke-y.
Thank you.
[ Laughs ]
SERVER:
Citrus avocado poké.
So, if you watch
"Guy's Big Bite"
and when we cook in
my backyard in my kitchen,
the big, huge wooden pergola
that protects us,
built by this dude
right here!
One of my good buddies,
Fernando, and his wife, Abra.
What do you think
of the poké?
On this island, there are
a few different places
that do it very well.
This is one of them.
-Fresh fish?
-Fresh, it's always good.
One shrimp and grits.
It is truly outstanding food.
-Ribs and chicken.
-Foster's Kitchen is by far
the best restaurant
on the big island.
So, under this hat, man,
I put a little Guy
on the side there.
FIERI: Does that say "Triple D"
on there, too?
"Triple D" on there.
[ Both laugh ]
I have seen it all.
[ Laughs ]
It's all right here,
right now, on his head.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next,
in Alameda, California...
Not my first rodeo.
...a joint slopping
surprises on a standard...
This is not
a mamby-pamby burger.
...and I'm bringing
in a heavy hitter
for some spicy bird.
Really good, huh?
Smacking!
♪♪
So, I'm right outside
of Oakland, California
on an island known
as Alameda right on the bay.
So, you find yourself
on Park Street,
and you're looking
for a place to eat.
I hear there's a little sandwich
and burger joint
that's got a real commitment
to excellence.
You got to check it out.
This is Scolari's.
♪♪
BOYD: We have a Good Ol' Boy
Nashville Hot.
Scolari's has some
of the most amazing food.
Traditional, but it's
a nice flair to it.
Falafel burger up.
It's really delicious.
Innovative.
FIERI:
And the man behind it all
is Chef Mike Boyd,
a restaurant vet who's been
cooking since he was a kid.
BOYD: Some of the kitchens
that I worked in
were a lot higher-end
than what this place seems,
but we take
familiar-sounding food
and do it the best we can.
It doesn't have
to be white tablecloth,
but you're taking
quality ingredients,
and treating them
the right way,
and using the best
techniques you can.
Yeah.
And you can dive
into that grub
right here at Scolari's
or next door.
You come in,
you order your food,
and we deliver it to the bar
that's right next door.
Take the food out
the door, in the bar.
In the bar.
Right next door.
Hear it every day.
They care
about their customers.
Who don't want to have
a beer with their burger?
Blueberry burger and
scampi fries in the window.
The blueberry blue cheese
bacon burger is phenomenal.
WOMAN #3:
I know it sounds weird,
but it's the best combination
of flavors.
All right,
so what are we making?
We're gonna make
our blueberry bacon
blue cheese burger au poivre.
You got me
at hello, Chef.
[ Chuckles ]
Let's roll.
We got our fresh blueberries,
fresh lemon juice,
sugar,
and a pinch of salt.
We add our cornstarch slurry
to thicken everything up.
Now, are we looking
for these blueberries
to really break down,
or do we want to have
a little texture to them?
We're gonna leave the berries
so they're whole.
The next part
of this adventure is?
We're gonna
fire our burger.
Angus beef?
Yes.
We're gonna salt it, roll it
in the coarse black pepper.
Then we're gonna throw it
on the grill.
All right,
Chef, all right.
Scampi fries.
So good old-fashioned
French fries that we all love,
that we usually
add ketchup to.
Yeah.
Instead, you do what?
We finish
with a scampi sauce.
We've got our chopped
fresh garlic,
fresh lemon juice,
lemon zest.
A little wango-tango?
Yeah. Salt,
black pepper,
olive oil.
I'm gonna give it
a little twirl.
"Twirl" is what you
wanted to go with, huh?
Yeah, twirl.
I couldn't think
of anything else.
"Mix" is always
a fun one.
"Marry."
"Marry" is another one.
"Amalgamate."
Ooh, that's a good one.
I don't know how
to spell that word.
We double-cook
our fries.
We're gonna salt them up.
Good, fat pinch
of chili flake.
Marry our ingredients again.
Re-acclimate.
Yes.
We're gonna
give them a toss.
Finish them with
a little chopped parsley.
♪♪
Good fry, buddy.
Now for our burger.
Basil aioli.
On a brioche.
We're gonna take
our burger patty
that's been crusted
with the peppercorn.
And blue cheese
blueberry sauce,
apple wood smoked bacon,
slice of red onion,
big pinch of arugula,
and we're gonna pick it.
And that's the burger.
Wow, man.
That's good.
You got the smash down.
This isn't your first rodeo.
-Not my first rodeo.
♪♪
Mm-hmm. The thing that
I get right off the bat,
which I love,
is the black peppercorn.
♪♪
Oh!
That peppercorn crust,
and a little bit
of that blueberry,
and the richness
of the blue cheese,
and a little of that raw onion
on top of that.
Chef, I like it.
[ Laughs ]
Really good burger.
Delicious fries.
You pushed the culinary
boundary a little bit.
This is not
a mamby-pamby burger.
I don't know
what "mamby-pamby" means.
[ Laughs ]
But it sounded right.
It did.
Just a culinary rock concert
between two buns.
SERVER: I have your blueberry
burger here for you.
It's a really innovative
use of flavors.
It's like, boom!
Once you bite it,
it explodes in your mouth.
The scampi fries are excellent.
I love the intenseness of
the garlic. It's, like, "Wow!"
What do you got
for me next?
I got --
Well, hang on, hang on.
Before you tell me,
I got a special friend
that's coming over.
I mean, this dude is Oaktown.
When we come back,
I hear there's a sandwich
we got to try.
There is.
Hot chicken, baby.
If you're looking for some heat,
it's a good way to go.
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back. We are hanging out
with rap artist E-40.
We're at Scolari's.
We're in Alameda.
When you think about Oaktown,
this is the guy you think about.
Now, born in Vallejo,
but this is his roots.
The yay area.
[ Laughing ]
"The yay area."
The yay area.
There we go.
I figured I'd bring
him in for a little
Nashville Hot chicken,
and we'll make it happen.
I might have to get
something on this, though,
'cause I don't want
to see any of the sauce
dripping down on the 40.
That's nothing.
I'll go buy another one.
[ Both laugh ]
♪♪
SERVER:
Good Ol' Boy Nashville Hot.
MAN #2:
The Good Ol' Boy Nashville Hot
is absolutely amazing.
Great heat with a little bit
of sweetness to it.
Every bite is just wonderful.
We start with
a super simple brine.
Just salt and water.
A marinade will go about
a quarter-inch into the chicken,
but a brine will go
all the way through...
Yes, sir.
...adding a ton of flavor
into that chicken.
And we're gonna
let them go overnight.
Next up?
All right, we're gonna
make a simple spice mix.
Kosher salt,
fresh ground black pepper,
a little
granulated garlic.
We're gonna take
the chicken out of the brine.
Season our chicken.
-Now into the flour dredge.
-We're gonna lay it 15 minutes
after they've had
their first dredge.
Okay.
And then we're gonna
re-dredge them,
so they're nice
and extra crispy.
This guy takes
everything so serious.
Yeah.
Means a lot.
We're gonna fry this chicken
for about 8 or 9 minutes.
300 degrees.
So it's dark meat.
It's gonna take a little bit
longer to cook
to really make sure it goes
all the way through.
So let's talk about
Nashville Hot chicken.
One of the keys
to the whole thing
is whatever the sauce is
you're gonna put on it.
Now, Chef,
you make your own.
Yeah.
Okay,
give me the rundown.
We start with the hot hot.
We got cayenne pepper.
[ Whispering ]
That's a lot of cayenne.
That a lot
of cayenne.
Little brown sugar to tone
it down a little bit.
Chili powder, garlic powder,
paprika.
And then to bring out
all those flavors.
[ Normal voice ]
And to bring it all together.
Some hot oil.
That's gonna toast
all those spices.
Interesting.
You got your hot sauce.
And the only thing
we got left to do
is what, Chef?
Pickle the jalapeños.
Take it easy on us.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'll take it easy.
Start with
some white vinegar.
Little bit of water
to cut that acid.
Cider vinegar, salt,
crushed garlic,
toasted peppercorns,
bay leaf.
This is interesting.
Little turmeric.
Gives them
a nice color.
Little bit of oil,
and then some Mexican oregano.
Let that come up to a boil.
-All right.
And then we're gonna put
some julienned onions
over the top of the jalapeños
and chopped carrots.
And 24 hours
to pickle this?
24 hours.
I like it, man.
That on top of a sandwich
is gonna be legit.
That looks great.
Some chicken.
Give them the hot bath.
I'll take the hot bath.
[ Chuckles ]
Toasted brioche.
Mayonnaise.
Lettuce.
Here's the hot.
House pickles made pretty much
the same way as the jalapeño.
-Hello.
-Pickled jalapeño.
And there we have it.
Now, with all the bling
and the nice beige shirt.
I don't want you
to wear any of this.
I'm gonna teach you the hunch.
-[ Chuckles ]
-Okay?
-Where my chef jacket at?
Are you jealous?
Getting after it.
So you give it a little pat.
-Mm-hmm.
-Get up underneath that.
♪♪
Mmm.
This ain't playing.
Really good, huh?
Smacking.
The fact that you're
cooking that chicken at 300
really gives
that dark-meat chicken
a chance to cook
all the way through,
and you really spend the time
to get that skin crispy.
I mean,
that skin is crispy.
Crispy.
Then the pickled
jalapeños.
Little bit of that extra fat
coming in from the mayo.
That's one of the best
fried chicken sandwiches
we've ever had on the show.
This the best one
I've had, period.
SERVER: I have your Good Ol' Boy
Nashville Hot here for you.
It's really tender. It doesn't
feel greasy and heavy.
It's just very tasty.
-Delicious?
-Delicious.
It's hot, it's spicy,
but it's also sweet and savory.
I don't think you can go
to any other restaurant
and get a chicken burger
like this.
Texas cheese steak
in the window.
The food is delicious,
and I try to eat it
whenever possible.
I've done a lot of things on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
but to have E-40
right now,
in Alameda, right outside
of Oakland, in a chef coat,
eating a Nashville Hot
chicken sandwich...
[ Chuckles ]
...that is right up top.
[ Laughs ]
Chef.
Great job.
Thank you.
All his little maneuvers.
All his little techniques.
All little behind-the-scenes
things that he's doing.
Mm-hmm.
That's why
he's crushing it.
FIERI: Coming up in Seattle...
I like it!
...a French chef's
slaying the Italian....
You do anything
that you want to do.
...and cooking chicken
with his native touch.
I knew what was
going on here, folks.
[ Beep ]
Any right here?
Hm?
We good?
I'll roll with it.
[beep]
♪♪
FIERI:
I'm in West Seattle, Washington.
Man, I love the Northwest.
Great coffee scene,
great music scene.
and a great food scene,
and I'm not surprised
to find out
that they've got a French chef
that's doing wood-fired
Italian pizza and a lot more.
This is Pizzeria Credo.
Linguine Alfredo,
order up.
Everything we've ever eaten here
is amazing.
SERVER: I've got
your Con Carne pizza.
This is like coming
to someone's home.
It's so welcoming.
It's so warm.
It's just a fun place to be.
FIERI: That's because
for French chef Jacques Nawar,
it's all about bringing
European hospitality and flavor
to the Pacific Northwest.
You're from France,
but you --
Yeah,
I was consulting,
and I came to Seattle,
I said, "I'm staying."
And here you are.
Here I am.
-You have the wood-fired oven.
-Yes.
-You also do sous vide.
-Mm-hmm.
Pasta. You do anything
that you want to do.
Yes.
I like it!
SERVER: Okay, tagliatelle
a la Bolognese.
I get Bolognese at every
Italian restaurant I go to,
and this is my favorite one.
The pasta's homemade.
The sauce is homemade.
Let's get started.
We're gonna start
with pasta.
Make it happen,
captain.
First, we're gonna
crack the eggs.
Oil, pinch of salt,
put the flour,
and the water.
Looks like little gravel
right now.
There it is!
Voilà.
Voilà!
Let it rest?
Yes.
Half an hour,
then we'll take it?
We're gonna make
it smaller.
Going through
the multiple layers.
Okay?
Yes.
See, teamwork?
Yes, indeed.
Give it a little flour.
Is that one order?
A couple orders.
Thank goodness.
You know,
we got to keep it --
Too much carbs.
And this is gonna go together
for a Bolognese?
Yes.
Do they eat a lot of
Bolognese in France?
Yeah, ragout.
Let's make the ragout.
Olive oil, extra virgin,
garlic.
Ground beef?
We're gonna add
the Angus beef lifter.
So great fat,
great flavor in that.
We're gonna stir it.
Work out some muscles.
♪♪
Tomato.
Great.
♪♪
See?
Mirepoix.
Celery, carrots,
and onions.
Beef stock,
white wine, salt,
bay leaves,
smoked paprika, pepper.
BOTH: Basil.
How long this gonna
cook down, Chef?
Minimum one hour
till it's reduced.
Okay.
-What we're gonna do now...
-Let's see it.
...tagliatelle.
So typically
you can't cook pasta
in this little bit
of water like this...
Yes.
...but because it's fresh pasta,
it's gonna go fast.
Couple minutes, yeah.
On with the Bolognese.
Shaved Parmesan cheese,
basil.
Some edible flowers.
Bon appétit.
Usually when people
say "bon appétit,"
I can't -- You know,
they're not able to say it.
He can say it.
He's French.
♪♪
The pasta
is perfect al dente.
A really good Bolognese
is very simple.
Yeah.
The balance
is perfect between
the salt and the sweet
of the mirepoix.
What really gets me
the best, though...
Mm-hmm.
...is the tender texture
of the meat.
If you're gonna eat
all those carbs,
it better be
really good.
Well done, my friend.
-Spot on.
All righty, guys.
Tagliatelle Bolognese.
The Bolognese is great.
Tasty noodles.
WOMAN #3:
You really get the meat flavor.
It's one of my favorite dishes
to get here.
Coming up, linguine.
MAN #3: Jacques uses
a lot of good techniques
that he's brought over. He's
able to put into his dishes.
FIERI: Including sous vide.
So, sous vide
is to vacuum seal
your vegetables
or your proteins,
and then throw them
in an immersion circulator.
Cook it at a precise
temperature. Bring it out.
It's cooked all the way through
the exact same temperature.
I have the chicken Vallée d'Auge
for you.
Oh, this chicken Vallée d'Auge
is flavorful and rich.
WOMAN #4:
The chicken is very tender,
and apples on top of it
add something special.
NAWAR: Now we're gonna make
chicken Vallée d'Auge.
So we take
the chicken breasts.
Yeah.
Salt.
Piment d'Espelette.
Oh, that's just what
I thought it was.
Yeah.
It's French red pepper.
So we're gonna drop this
into the vacuum sealer?
Yes.
Let's do it.
How long are these
gonna go in?
40 minutes.
What are we gonna do
after we remove them?
It's already cooked,
so we're gonna sear it.
All we're gonna do.
We're gonna throw
some shallots, apple,
champignon de Paris,
and shiitake mushroom.
Little salt, pepper,
and Calvados.
So, an apple brandy?
Yep.
Voilà.
Voilà!
I knew what was
going on here, folks!
Yeah.
Cider.
-Little bit of heavy cream?
-Heavy cream, yes.
Melt it
with some more butter.
Now we're gonna add
the chicken back.
And that's it.
Sliced apple,
the mushroom.
There's a little paprika
on the corner.
Yeah.
I can't say that there's been
very many times in "Triple D,"
that we've done
sous vide.
But one of
the beauties of sous vide,
it's cooked evenly
all the way.
And you want to talk about
the most tender chicken breast
that you've ever had
a chance to bite into.
Yes.
Perfectly cooked
to the right temperature.
And it's so funny how...
...we love pork
and apples.
I don't typically
have chicken.
Yeah.
With a little bit
of the sweetness
and a little tartness.
-Makes a great combination.
Delicious.
Thank you.
SERVER: All right, I've got
the chicken Vallée d'Auge.
It's flavorful, but it's light.
Very tender, hearty. Very good.
NAWAR: Meatball al Forno.
Pizzeria Credo's
is one of our favorites.
It's delicious. It's fresh.
That's why I keep coming back.
I thought
when I walked in
I was coming
to a pizza restaurant.
Yeah?
There's a lot more
going on.
Well done, Chef.
Thank you.
So, that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry!
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives"!
I actually met you
a long time ago.
I got in an elevator,
I turned around,
and you right there
behind me.
I was like,
"Man, I love your show."
And you shook my hand.
And I was just like,
"Oh, my God. I can't believe
he's here!" [ Laughs ]
FIERI: And look what happened.
We meet 4,000 miles away.
[ Laughs ]