I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're going to Round 2,
revisiting some of our favorite
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning.
[ Laughter ]
Because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up.
Did you see that?
And we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
Oh, that's good.
A Miami spot holding the title
as culinary dojo of Flavortown.
I'm a wreck
for some neck.
I had to.
A noodle shop in Portland
still going strong...
The guy's got a gun.
Look at this guy.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: ...whipping out homemade
dumplings by the dozen.
What makes a good burger?
You got to have creativity.
And a joint in Spokane
exploding with new dishes.
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, here we are
in South Beach, Miami,
to visit a good buddy of mine
from a funky little joint
we did on "Triple D"
called Sakaya.
♪♪
Sakaya is sexy fast food.
It's Asian soul food.
Korean fried chicken wings.
FIERI: Chef, you've been
blowing it up.
You're doing a Korean
Asian-inspired
funkalicious joint.
♪♪
[ Laughs ] Welcome to the
culinary dojo in Flavortown!
Give me a "Heeyah."
Heeyah!
FIERI: When I first met
Richard Hales in 2014,
he was putting a whole
new spin on fusion...
Pickup, duck sandwich.
...like with this
Cracklin' Herb Duck Sandwich.
Dredge it in the flour
lightly.
And then it goes
straight into the fryer.
-Three, four minutes?
-Yeah.
Nice.
And what are we
dropping this into?
This is our
honey-orange sauce --
so star anise, cinnamon,
with honey and oranges.
This whole thing
comes off.
Whoa!
Who let the duck out?
This is the ssamjang.
Pick our meat.
That's ridiculous.
Take a little spicy mayo.
A little bit
of scallions.
We make these quick pickles,
fresh cilantro.
Let's get into
this sandwich.
♪♪
It's deep. It's rich.
It's spicy. It's tangy.
It's silky. It's fresh.
It's vibrant.
It's, I mean...
That's like
my whole vocabulary.
I can't even spell
most of the words.
Game over.
It's out of bounds.
But his cooking wasn't the only
thing that made that
"Triple D" visit unforgettable.
I drive up to do
the "Triple D" joint.
I jump out of the car,
and I see this beautiful Caddy.
Is that your Caddy
across the street?
-Yeah.
-Is it for sale?
In the entire time through
the process of doing "Triple D,"
I'm hitting him
about the Caddy.
How long you want
your segment to be?
[ Laughter ]
Hey, we're here,
and that was great.
HALES: We start with
the raw duck legs.
You know what I'm missing?
Something in this hand,
like keys.
I'm missing keys
in this hand.
Hold on a second.
Here you go.
Somebody bring the title!
I bought it, shipped it back
to California.
At the moment,
when I handed you the keys,
a loan shark had the title.
-No!
-I swear to God.
-I swear.
-Seriously?
-Yes.
-How did I get played?
I don't get played
like that!
Oh, you're killing me.
At least the money
was well-spent
because just four years later,
Sakaya's still killing it,
and Richard hasn't slowed down.
Right across the street
from Sakaya,
he's got a funky joint
called The Black Brick.
I've been dying to eat it.
Let's go try.
WOMAN:
He's come up with some dishes
that I haven't found in
any other Chinese restaurant.
Two Dan-Dans, Table 4.
So talk to me about this.
So, how do you describe
Black Brick?
Similar to Sakaya but only
focusing on Chinese food.
Give me the greatest hits.
The first thing we're gonna do
is some duck necks and heads.
So we do
Peking Duck here.
When you eat Peking Duck,
it's all about the skin.
-Right.
-So that's all there is on
the neck and the head,
is skin.
FIERI: Now, most restaurants
would chop the neck off
the Peking Duck and toss 'em,
but not this dude.
I chopped it up, but some spice
blend that we have already here.
I tasted it.
I'm like, "Oh, this is good."
So we started selling.
I thought nobody would buy it,
and we cannot keep these in.
That's good, man.
They sell out every time
we put them on the menu.
I mean, I'm a wreck
for some neck.
-[ Chuckles ]
-I had to.
I want you to think
about duck chicharrones.
Little fatty, not much.
Nice crunch.
Look at that.
Those are good.
All right,
what do we got here?
These are our fried
chicken dumplings.
Okay, so he's not
making you any?
[ Laughs ]
So it's chicken thigh --
organic, local -- garlic chives.
Dude,
that is packed full.
Yeah.
These are ridiculous,
all right?
Don't come down
and have one of these.
Come down
and have nine of them.
I heard about the dumplings
in this place,
and I had to have
the experience.
It has a lot of flavor.
They're amazing.
What was it like after
"Triple D" hit Sakaya?
I didn't know a lot about
the effect of the show,
to be honest with you,
but you told me,
"Hey, be ready."
I told you to be ready.
I didn't know anything
about this.
♪♪
Those people that come in that
are big followers of the show,
they love to see us
in person.
It's very friendly,
and it's nice.
"What did you guys
talk about?
Did he really buy the car?"
-Right. Right.
What are we trying next?
This is Mala Chicken,
so M-A-L-A,
which is hot and numbing.
"Hot and numbing"
is what it means?
Yeah.
FIERI: It's loaded with
all kinds of chilies,
but it's the numbing oil
that takes it over the top.
You get all that
Szechuan chili.
♪♪
So you know how the big
Szechuan peppercorns
kind of make your tongue
a little bit numb,
kind of make it dance?
Totally happening
right now.
Oh, that's good.
[ Laughs ]
Just like Sakaya, dude.
The food's so legit.
♪♪
You build solid concepts.
You're a true chef.
You're all big-time now.
-No.
Dude's big-time.
And the car I bought from
Richard, yeah, I still got it.
And while he's going gangbusters
with his restaurants, well,
I'm -- I'm still trying
to get that car on the road.
Now, speaking of
going gangbusters...
[ Mumbles ]
[ Laughs ]
Coming up,
in Portland, Oregon,
a noodle shop that had
to break new ground
to keep up with the crowds.
That guy's got a gun!
♪♪
Back in 2013, I checked out
this small noodle shop
that was literally an old house
on a busy street in Portland.
Now the place has a second,
much bigger location,
but the food
is still the real deal.
This is Frank's Noodle House.
♪♪
I've been coming
since we saw it on
"Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
It's fresh vegetables,
fresh noodles done well
and with a lot of love.
Kung Pao Chicken
with noodles.
WOMAN: It's so nice.
You can just anytime
come into
a very authentic
Chinese restaurant.
Everything is so fresh.
Chicken Noodle ready!
FIERI: Owner Frank Fong learned
to cook from his grandma
in Northwest China
when he was just 10 years old,
and he still uses
those same family recipes today.
I love Chinese food.
Thank you.
I could eat Chinese food
for breakfast...
Uh-huh.
...dinner,
in a car, at a bar,
in a boat, with a goat.
[ Chuckles ]
Are we gonna make
the noodle?
Yeah.
That's what
I'm looking for.
All-Purpose flour.
Yeah.
Get out!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
How long
do you knead this for?
That guy's got a gun!
[ Laughs ]
He said, "You should open a gym
in Frank's Noodle House."
Every day?
Every day.
Look at this guy.
[ Laughs ]
You should call it
Frank's Noodle House.
We call it
No!
Yeah.
Absolutely,
Frank's Noodle House.
Get out!
Yes!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
That's the noodle.
Boil it.
That's it?
Yeah.
Here,
I want to try this.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
This.
Again.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
This way.
Yeah.
Uh-oh.
I broke.
[ Chuckles ]
"It's broken."
[ Laughter ]
Not looking like Frank's.
That one was terrible,
Frank.
It's not gonna say Guy's Noodle
House if it keeps up like this.
Hot and fast, baby.
Put the chicken in here.
♪♪
Look at that!
Oh!
♪♪
Is it terrible?
Bad, man.
This is bad.
I better get this
all away from you.
[ Laughs ]
Boom.
Okay.
I think that maybe
he doesn't like it.
I tried to take
the dishes away.
[ Mumbles ]
[ Laughs ]
No, come back.
He just eat it, eat it,
eat it, eat it all.
Yeah.
After the show,
there were people
waiting in line on the street.
Very, very crazy.
Pork with napa cabbage.
FIERI:
Frank's business got so crazy,
he opened a bigger location
about 9 miles away in Beaverton.
Now that they opened
one literally down the street
from our house,
it's so convenient.
We can just walk over
for every meal of the day.
There are some new items since
they've opened this location
that they've added
to the menu.
FIERI: Which includes
familiar favorites
like General Tso's
and Kung Pao Chicken.
Plus, customers can't get
their hands
off his handmade
pork dumplings.
Every week, I make like
4,000 or 5,000 pieces.
A lot of work, but people
love the steamed dumplings.
Really good.
FIERI: And they're served with
a simple sauce
that's packing a big punch.
FONG: Red pepper.
Sugar.
Vinegar.
Soy sauce.
♪♪
You can taste that they're
handmade and they're made fresh.
The dipping sauce, I think it
enhances the flavor of the pork.
The dumplings --
they're the perfect size,
they're not too overpowering.
They don't fill you up
for your meal.
It's perfect.
FIERI:
Which is right where Frank's
family cookbook comes from,
and one of the highlights
is Mom's Napa Cabbage
and Pork Belly Specialty.
I learned from my grandma
and mom.
I really like that the pork
belly is really thinly sliced.
It's like a combination
of slightly spicy
and kind of a slightly sour,
salty taste.
Fresh vegetables,
fresh noodles.
Yeah.
Quality ingredients.
Yes.
I like that.
I didn't know "Triple D" before.
So after that, I watched
the show every day.
First Chinese restaurant in
Portland on the "Triple D" show.
So I was really,
really proud of myself.
Well, listen,
it's a great place.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You have a lot to be
very proud of, okay?
Thank you.
Thanks for having us.
I'm gonna come back.
Can I hug you?
Big hug. Okay?
Sure.
I love this guy.
I hear Frank is looking
for even more locations.
Now, listen, Frank, I'm just
gonna throw it out there.
Don't take it as --
Hey, how about
Northern California?
Call me, Frank.
And next up...
And go!
...a joint in Spokane still
knockin' it out of the park
with their tricked-out
burgers...
You should call that that
The Ridiculous Burger.
...and bringing in new fans
to check out
their gigantic new brewpub.
In 2011, I checked out
this joint
in Spokane, Washington.
Now, they have 35 beers on tap
and one-of-a-kind
sandwiches and burgers.
-Order up!
-Fast-forward to today,
and they've upped their game --
a new location, a brewery, and
even more outrageous creations.
This is Waddell's
Brewpub & Grille.
♪♪
You can't go wrong
with the food here.
Whether you come for
a macaroni-and-cheese, burger,
or anything in between,
it's awesome.
MAN: This must be
a really good place
because Guy only goes
to good places, I've seen.
MAN #2:
I saw this place on "Triple D."
I think I've had everything
on the menu since.
MAN #3: Rube Waddell Burger
with French fries!
FIERI: This joint was named
after baseball hall-of-famer
Rube Waddell, who had a love
for beer and dynamite food.
And owners Michael and Skip,
they share that passion.
Was it always the plan
of beer and burgers?
NOBLE: Skip and I love beer,
we love good food.
Married them together, and this
is what we came up with.
People say the word "burger,"
and they think "Ah,
cheeseburger,
bacon cheeseburger,
double cheeseburger."
But you've taken burgers
to a whole new level.
And that would be the
understatement of the century.
What makes a good burger?
You got to have creativity.
Sweet and Tangy Burger.
There It Is Burger.
Rube Waddell Burger.
[ Mumbles ]
A burger with corned beef,
sauerkraut, bacon,
and Swiss, named after
the Great Waddell himself.
♪♪
You went to all this trouble
to name it after Rube Waddell.
You better back it up
with the sandwich
that's got all that energy
and enthusiasm.
And that right there
is the bad boy.
Little did I know, that was
just the lead-off hitter.
Nothing could have prepared me
for the beast of a burger,
the Big Dawgg.
Burger time!
All right,
Big Dawgg time.
Let's do it.
So the rancher patty's
got the pork in it
and all the seasoning,
and then an 80/20.
Good flavors
in both burgers.
Toasted bun.
Pepper Jack and Cheddar.
Put some ham
in between the burgers.
The barbecue mayo.
Onion rings.
Some jalapeños.
FIERI: Oh, come on, now!
You got to have it.
Stack it on there.
Bacon on top.
Lid it, stab it.
That's
the Big Dawgg Burger.
You should call that that
The Ridiculous Burger.
Ready? And go!
I took a wimpy bite,
and he called me out on it.
What, did your sister
take a bit of that?
So I took another big bite.
There you go.
Got it all over my face.
[ Laughs ]
Had a good laugh about it.
Do I have any sauce?
Here?
What are you trying
to say?
Is this enough?
Oh, the napkin!
I thought he was a mess.
[ Laughs ]
We get people coming from all
over the United States
who said they saw us
on the show and they said,
"I love the look of that
Big Dawgg Burger
or the Rube Waddell Burger."
Or it was, "We need to come
and have that Irish Lamb Dip.
What's up next?
Leg of lamb.
Some bacon grease.
Oh!
Love that
smoky good flavor.
Now, what do we call
this lamb-strosity?
This is
the Irish Lamb Dip.
Lamb-strosity.
Could we change the name
to Lamb-strosity?
Okay, for you.
The "Triple D"
Lamb-strosity.
I like it.
We changed the menus, I think,
the day after he left,
and it's been called
"Lamb-strosity" ever since.
Let that cook a little bit.
Toast the bun.
Some cheddar cheese goes
really good with this lamb.
All right.
Put a little bit of Waddell
mayo on there.
Mayo with teriyaki sauce.
Put that on there,
nice and juicy.
♪♪
Right on point.
I can chug the au jus.
Those that really like lamb
will really enjoy this.
And even if they don't think
they like lamb,
I challenge them to try this
and tell me they don't dig it.
Now, if you think that lamb
sandwich was the bomb...
MAN: Smokehouse Briskit!
We wanted to add
something else to our menu.
FIERI: ...take cover, 'cause
things are about to explode.
That is the craziest thing
I've ever seen.
FIERI: It's been seven years
since I bit into my first
Big Dawgg burger at
Waddell's Brewpub & Grille
in Spokane, Washington.
Ready? And go!
Now, here,
owners Michael and Skip
are known for their giant
jaw-breaking burgers,
but those skills
don't stop at the grill.
Apparently, they can work
with fire and ice.
WOMAN: Wow!
That is the craziest thing
I've ever seen.
Stay cool.
But like for a lot
of restaurants,
the beginning was tough.
You dumped everything into this.
-Yes.
Our life, hard work.
Everything.
You put it all on red.
It's all on red.
Rube Waddell Burger
with French fries!
-Putting it all on Waddell's.
-On Waddell's.
Right when
the recession opened.
Nice!
Yes.
That's what I like to do,
just jump right in.
Yeah.
Just jump right in.
You know,
when the pond's shallow.
Exactly.
You know?
Watch out for those rocks.
Exactly.
We ended up opening
in January of 2008.
What happened then was The Great
Recession, and it was hard.
In 2011, right after
the show aired,
we knew that we were
gonna need more help.
We decided, "Hey,
we need to branch out.
We're doing really well here."
We just didn't have
enough seats for people.
-Thank you.
FIERI: And bigger business
turned into a bigger place
with enough room to seat
over 300 people
and start brewing
their own beer.
NOBLE:
We do two menus a year --
a new one for spring
and a new one for fall.
FIERI:
But their candy-covered wings
are a year-round crowd pleaser.
These things literally blow up.
NOBLE:
We're making our chipotle pepper
base for our hot wing sauce.
So, smoked Paprika,
Squirrelly Rancher seasoning,
salt, sugar, cumin blend,
garlic powder, onion powder,
hot sauce, chipotle peppers
in an adobe sauce --
nice earthy flavors.
Just makes the sauce
taste perfect.
[ Blender whirs ]
I'm gonna add our chipotle
base sauce here.
Nice good kick to it.
FIERI: But the real kicker
is the candy.
[ Candy crackling ]
NOBLE: It's just a fun novelty
kind of thing,
but it also tastes good
at the same time.
They're not too spicy,
and just before you swallow,
you get the pop explosions
in your mouth.
Makes it go down
even sweeter.
MAN #2: The sweetness
with the spiciness,
you'd think it'd be
kind of a weird taste,
but it's really good.
Almost like you think
it's just gonna be delicious,
but it's fun and delicious.
MAN #3: Coming up with a
Smokehouse Briskit Sandwich.
FIERI: But if you're looking for
more of a meal,
they're piling on with
the Smokehouse Briskit Sandwich.
We love to do everything
in-house by scratch.
FIERI:
I had their housemade lamb
on their Lamb-Strosity Sandwich,
and I had their housemade corned
beef on the Rube Waddell Burger.
So now I hear that they're
smokin' their own brisket,
and everybody says
it's out of bounds.
Smokehouse Briskit,
and it's the number-one seller
here at Waddell's.
MAN: Smokehouse Briskit!
FIERI:
It starts with housemade brisket
and Mike's homemade
barbecue sauce.
Right away, I'm getting
that hickory,
I'm getting
that Cayenne pepper.
The honey,
a good sweetness to it.
And then we have that dry
mustard and regular mustard --
really good
for barbecue sauce.
Now we're gonna take
the chopped brisket.
So we're putting it
in a container
so that we can mix
our barbecue sauce that we made.
Drizzle a nice amount on there,
let that brisket soak.
Now we're ready for the flat-top
to build the sandwich.
[ Sizzling ]
It's very delicious when it
comes all together
with the smoked Gouda on top.
Very, very good.
-Enjoy.
-The brisket is so amazing.
You can taste the smokiness,
you can taste the tanginess
of the barbecue sauce.
The sauce is not too sweet.
It's really flavorful and good.
The brisket is smoky, tender,
juicy, and delicious.
♪♪
Let me tell you something --
Being a restaurant owner myself,
it starts with taking
great care of people,
serving quality product,
giving a good price,
and being here all the time
working your butt off,
and I got to tell you something,
man, you're on your way.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You guys, get down here
before this place gets packed.
There's already a line
out the door.
So, there you have it --
a Miami chef
who's knocking it
out big-time,
a Chinese noodle shop
that's gone times two,
and a pub that's delivering
Major League dishes,
and what do you get?
It's called "Triple D Nation."
It's all 'cause of you.
And, don't worry,
there's over 1,100 joints.
We got a lot more to check out.
See you next week.
This is flour.
Okay. Wheat flour.
I thought
that was a duck.
[ Laughter ]
Twins.