Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
This trip...
Yes, yes, yes.
...we're transporting
your taste buds...
This is what "Triple D's"
all about.
...on an epic
culinary journey.
I don't even need
a passport.
We've got island fever
in Kona...
It's a Filipino-
Hawaiian-American concept
with his own twist.
...incredible Indonesian
in Oregon.
I've never had that
before.
And in Chicago...
Come on now, up top.
...a taste of Spain
that reigns supreme.
Sister, this is Flavortown,
without question.
Delicious.
That's all right here,
right now,
on Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Chicago in the
Lake View East neighborhood,
right across the street
from Lincoln Park neighborhood,
to check out a joint that,
I gotta tell you,
is in a basement.
What's going on here?
Well, a husband-and-wife
team are knocking out
some Spanish tapas
that you won't forget.
Slow down, look around,
it's right here at mfk.
♪♪
SARI: Boquerones and bread.
I think that
Chicago has the most
interesting food
scene in the country.
This place is a shining
example of that.
30 seconds on tortilla.
mfk. is this gem that serves
coastal Spanish cuisine.
SARI:
Croquettes and a ceviche.
They really focus on the
seafood. It's spectacular.
FIERI: Not what you'd expect
from the shores
of Lake Michigan.
But no surprise when you
meet chefs and owners
Scott and Sari Worsham, who
are packing a culinary punch.
I worked for Chef
Charlie Trotter for 13 years.
FIERI: Oh! One of the greatest
in the world.
You were in the
business forever.
Since 1988.
I started in
Santa Rosa, actually.
-Santa Rosa, California?
-Yeah.
Is this "Guy Fieri:
This Is Your Life"?
I understand you know
the area somewhat.
A bit.
I came back
to Santa Rosa and opened
my first restaurant
in '96.
FIERI: And when this
couple opened
their joint in Chicago,
they modeled it after places
they loved when
they visited Spain.
SCOTT: We wanted to do something
that had real simple,
non-fussy food that tastes
delicious and make people happy.
We got our seafood
fideos here for ya.
MAN: Today, I'm enjoying
the seafood fideo.
Absolutely delectable.
Shrimp cooked perfectly.
Noodles with really creamy sauce
that brings it all together.
-What are we making?
-Our seafood fideos.
You go to Spain,
everybody's got
their own little style of it.
How's yours?
Like paella, but with
pasta instead of rice.
We take the angel hair
pasta, roast it in the oven
for about 20,
30 minutes at 400,
and cook the pasta
till it's al dente.
We're on to?
We're gonna make
the piperade.
Put a little oil
in the pan.
And then we cook our
peppers a bit first.
Add a little salt to help
the peppers sweat the water.
Gonna start
that caramelization faster
and building
layers of flavor.
Yellow onions,
sliced garlic.
And why sliced
versus minced?
We're cooking this for
a good amount of time,
and the minced seems
to get a little burnt.
The longer the cooking
process, the larger the garlic.
-You got it.
-Come on now, up top.
All right.
Piquillo peppers and
the roasted poblanos.
Sherry vinegar.
Most underutilized
vinegar there is.
Red chili flake,
paprika.
-Smoked?
-It is.
A little bit more salt,
pepper,
and then we just let
this cook together
for another minute or two
to wake up the spices.
Okay, and the final
step of this will be?
You get the fideos rocking
in the oil.
I thought the song
was "Rock Me Amadeus."
"Rock Me --"
It's "Rock Me Fideos."
Never knew that.
So, we sauté some
shallots, minced garlic,
pinch of salt, our piperade,
the head-on prawns cooked
for about a minute...
Love it.
...on each side.
Add the pasta.
Lot going on right now.
We've got our saffron
vegetable stock,
and you can probably
smell it.
It's just delish.
-Oh, it's gorgeous.
Cream,
we'll add our mussels.
Let those open.
Little bit of lemon
juice, parsley,
and then she's ready
for prime time.
We're gonna go
into our fancy pot,
and then we'll add our prawns,
and then a little herb.
There we go.
♪♪
Mmm.
It's awesome,
really great.
I mean,
it's a delicious dish.
♪♪
The cooking of the
mussels in the dish,
little bloom of the saffron,
little touch of the herb,
and the citrus at the end,
all the little steps.
I'm having this total
flashback of being in Spain.
Sister, this is Flavortown,
without question.
Delicious.
SERVER: Seafood fideos.
Toasting the noodles
is something that
you don't get often, and that
really makes a difference.
There's also a lot of
different spices in it,
different notes and
different tones.
Forget all
the madness outside.
Have some fideo
and have a porron.
FIERI: Now that's what
I'm talking about.
The porron is Spanish
tradition all the way
when it comes to drinking wine.
Let me see, here we go.
Let me see.
Nicely done.
-Oh!
Huh, did I catch it?
The minute that
you step in here,
it's a vacation and a party.
It reminds me of the Costa
Brava, the Spanish coast.
MAN #2:
You kind of immediately get that
with all of the food
that they have.
SARI: Crunchy prawns up.
MAN #2: I'm sure a lot of people
are kind of freaked out
by just a prawn head, but
the crunchy prawn heads
with the xató sauce,
it's tremendous.
In the appreciation
for Amaebi,
which is one of my
favorite sushi restaurants,
the sweet shrimp
is served raw
and then the head
is tempura-ed.
Similar to that idea?
Correct.
And this is a sauce
we're making for it?
Yes, this is a xató sauce
that's really great
to dip the prawn head
in and then pop it in.
[ Clicks tongue ]
We start with some dried
bread, Fresno chili peppers,
piquillo peppers,
lots of garlic,
grape or cherry tomatoes,
sliced shallots,
chopped chives and
parsley, some almonds.
Love almonds.
Now it's not gonna
be right.
It's probably wrecked
the whole dish.
Sherry vinegar, we got
a little honey, water,
kosher salt, and then
a couple tablespoons
of neutral oil, boom,
and crank her up.
Drop the hammer.
♪♪
Wow, that's good.
Little acid, little
sweet, little texture
from the bread and
from the almonds.
I don't care what
you put that on.
Steak, French fries,
chicken, I'm in.
Okay, that's the new name
of the restaurant.
Steak, French fries,
chicken, I'm in.
Hello.
Okay.
Now we're gonna make
our dry tempura batter.
We start off with
some baking powder,
cornstarch, cake flour,
makes it lighter,
kosher salt,
all-purpose flour.
Prawn heads go
in the sieve.
Shake her down.
Where were you last night?
Where's my money?
She's ready for the fryer.
Make it happen, captain.
-Crunchy prawn head.
-Yes, yes, yes.
So, we got
our xató sauce.
Put our
shrimp heads down.
Little torn basil, and then
we take our lemon wedge
and dip it in some
smoky paprika.
Fantastico.
I'll pick some basil
with it.
♪♪
This right here is meaty.
The head on this is
just enough shell
that it can fry and
it can get crispy.
It's like intensified
shrimp flavor
all brought together
with this fantastic sauce.
And just one more in
the name of science.
That's fantastic.
I have your crunchy
prawn heads for you.
They're just luscious.
The sauce is
absolutely phenomenal.
SARI: Ceviche crudo.
MAN #3: mfk.
is one of the spots,
if you're visiting Chicago,
that you absolutely
have to come to.
You have to try it out.
You guys are taking
your 6 tables
and 29 seats to a
whole nother level.
This is what "Triple D's"
all about,
finding these
funky little spots
by people that have this
love affair with food.
And that's what
you get at mfk.
Outstanding, well done.
-Thank you.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next, a wave of flavor
in Kailua-Kona, Hawaii...
You ain't wearing board
shorts after you eat this.
...at a spot making its name...
That's how you get
it done right there.
...on leaving you speechless.
Melt in your mouth.
You ever play bye-bye,
cellphone?
No, what's that?
You drop your cellphone in
and you say, "Bye-bye.
"Bye-bye, cellphone."
♪♪
I love bringing "Triple D"
to the islands.
Man, I've been to Oahu,
I've been to Maui,
I've been to Molokai.
Finally, I make it to
the Big Island of Hawaii.
So, what do I do
when I come here?
I'm looking for
some local's food.
That is, if you're
looking for some Filipino,
Hawaiian, American twist,
oh, I got your joint.
It's right here in
Broke Da Mouth Grindz.
♪♪
Three minutes on the burgers.
Food is always
delicious and on point.
Loco moco, ready.
Broke Da Mouth Grindz is
a favorite here in Kona
because they provide
a lot of local favorites.
Pork adobo plate
coming right up.
Every time you come here,
you're gonna get good food.
The service is great,
and I love the owners.
FIERI:
That would be husband and wife
Robin Ganir and Jean Nguyen,
who are mashing up
down-home food with
some faraway flavors.
GANIR: We make Filipino,
Hawaiian, American food
with a twist of my style.
Where'd you learn
to cook?
My family, they come
from a cooking background.
But it's
the backyard boogie.
Right,
with a dance move.
I went to Oahu,
got some schooling.
Came back
and did your own gig.
Yeah.
It's a new style of
cooking Hawaiian food.
Garlic furikake chicken.
Furikake chicken is so awesome.
WOMAN: It is like taking
the best piece of Southern
fried chicken
and upping it up a notch.
The sauce is, like, a sweet,
garlicky sauce
that is, like, amazing.
First we're gonna start with
the marinade for the chicken?
Yes, sir.
Soy sauce.
A little bit
of brown sugar.
Just 2 teaspoons
or 4 pounds.
[ Laughs ] 4 pounds.
White sugar,
black pepper.
A mess of garlic.
Furikake.
So you got the dried seaweed
and the sesame seeds.
Yeah, that's it.
You bring it to a boil
for three minutes.
Now we're gonna marinade
the chicken in this?
No, we're gonna
deep-fry it first.
We're gonna deep-fry
the chicken
and then put this on it?
-Yeah.
-Oh.
Boneless, but skin-on
chicken thighs
dusted in the flour, little
bit of granulated garlic.
Yeah, now our chicken
is ready to fry,
12 to 15 minutes.
-What temperature is the fryer?
-350.
In Hawaii, we say "tree."
-Tree hundred and 50.
Next up?
-Chili pepper watah.
-Chili watah.
Hawaiian rock salt,
minced garlic,
the sriracha,
sweet chili sauce,
and Hawaiian chili peppers.
Hit that with
an immersion blender.
And where's
this sauce gonna go?
It goes on everything.
It's gonna gave you
the tang, the sweet...
-The tang, the sweet.
-...and the heat.
It'll make you dance.
You don't want to see that.
Chicken fry's up.
Boom, it's done.
And we're just gonna
dip it into the sauce.
You just cut it up,
like so.
Three thighs.
Load it up, chef.
Just give it a extra
drizzle on top, furikake.
♪♪
That's how you get
it done right there.
Is this more Filipino
or more Hawaiian?
That's more
of a Hawaiian local.
That's my kind of
food right there.
All right.
The crunch of the chicken,
outstanding,
like, over the top.
The sweet that you're
getting from the dip...
with the soy, brown sugar,
and the garlic, it's great.
But it's the contrast
that you get
from the chili water,
makes it sing.
Ooh!
You ain't wearing board shorts
after you eat this.
You're in a muumuu.
-[ Laughs ]
The garlic furikake chicken.
The chicken is
absolutely incredible.
The sauce has this syrupy flavor
to it
with a real sweet back end.
It's super tender on the inside.
It's really crunchy.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-It's like a luau in your mouth.
Dancers and everything.
The animal cheeseburger.
This is the place
I always recommend.
If you like to eat
where the locals eat,
you gotta come to
Broke Da Mouth Grindz.
So, explain the name
to me.
GANIR:
This is from Hawaii.
Broke da mouth, that
means ono-licious food.
Ono means very good.
It's so good,
it's so delicious.
You never stop eating,
just keep going.
Chomp, chomp, chomp,
chomp, chomp.
Just eat it all.
What are the other big
hits here at the house?
We've got the braised
short ribs and shrimp.
SERVER:
Short ribs and shrimp.
The braised ribs
is always so moist.
The taste is out of this world.
FIERI:
And that's when we come back.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
I'm on the Big Island
at Broke Da Mouth.
I just had some fantastic
garlic chicken furikake...
FIERI: Cooked up
by chef Robin Ganir,
who's putting his mark
on this island menu.
Braised oxtail,
coming right up.
MAN #4: He puts a lot of
flavor into his food,
which makes it his own style.
I asked Chef, I said, "What's
the next dish gonna be?"
He says it's a Filipino-
Hawaiian-American concept
with his own twist.
Well, what's the dish
called?
Braised short ribs
and garlic shrimp.
The short ribs are
absolutely great.
It's got kind of
a caramelization to it.
It's really a sweet flavor.
All-time favorite,
garlic shrimp.
I don't know how they
keep the center so moist.
And the outside has this
little, crispy shell.
Let me see it happen,
buddy, what do you got?
GANIR: Beef short ribs,
we're gonna cut it.
In Hawaii,
we leave the fat on.
Okay, so from here,
where do we go?
We go straight on the
flat top and sear it off.
Next step?
-The braising liquid.
-Got it.
Gonna heat the pan up,
soy sauce in it,
brown sugar, some water.
Garlic.
Chopped-up white
onion, black pepper.
Black pepper.
You whisk this up.
Put the short ribs right inside
and simmer for two hours.
So that's just gonna
absorb all that flavor.
Melt in your mouth.
Short ribs are working.
What's up next?
Homemade garlic
aioli for the shrimp.
So, whole eggs.
Egg yolks.
I'll lick the bowl.
Okay. [ Laughs ]
Garlic, sweet chili.
I see a theme here.
Lemon juice, garlic
salt, black pepper.
We're gonna blend
it all together.
-And hit it with the oil?
-Yeah.
Tell me about the shrimp.
We just butterfly it,
put it in some flour,
and then we deep-fry it.
So, a light, quick fry.
There's our melted
garlic butter.
Great, a little bit
of the green onions,
the butter, the garlic.
We got
our braised short ribs.
You like fat?
-Do I like fat?
What are you looking at?
Yeah, I don't like that
at all.
All right.
Oh, those things are
right falling apart.
We hit it up with
some teriyaki glaze,
green onions,
homemade garlic aioli.
Gorgeous.
♪♪
This is a cross
between your favorite
teriyaki beef jerky and
your grandma's pot roast.
If you like short ribs,
that's your game right there.
And that soy sauce sugar,
garlic goes all the
way through that.
Now, what's up
with the potatoes?
Molokai sweet potato.
-Purple sweet potato?
-Yes, sir.
Where have I been
on that one?
That's a big shrimp for
a little funky food joint.
[ Laughs ] People ask
for extra aioli.
Of course they do.
You got so much flavor.
Cooked the shrimp
perfectly.
You make your own aioli,
make your marinades.
You really take time
to do things right.
I'm impressed. Well done.
-Thank you, Guy.
Ribs and shrimp.
The short ribs are sweet.
They just fall apart.
The flavor is just
exploding in your mouth.
Teriyaki barbecue chicken.
MAN #4: Well, if you're
on the Big Island
and you want to have a great
meal, this is the place.
You cannot leave Kona
without coming here.
Great food
treated with respect,
Hawaiian culture,
Filipino influence,
good old American twist
to it, but all you.
Yeah.
-Well done, my brother.
-Thank you.
Well done.
FIERI:
Coming up, in Ashland, Oregon...
Oh, it's going.
...a funky little piece
of the Pacific.
I should be able
to close my eyes
and teleport
to Indonesia.
...vouched for by none
other than my mother.
It's the bomb, right?
I told you.
It's the bomb.
♪♪
So, I'm here in beautiful
Ashland, Oregon.
And, like usual, I've
got everybody telling me
places I gotta check out,
except this time,
it's the red-headed wonder --
my mom, Penny.
Now, she says, "Guy, you
gotta check this place out.
Oh, my gosh, Guy,
the food is so fantastic.
Guy, our friends love
going to this place."
Are you guys ready for
my mom's recommendation?
This is Blue Toba.
♪♪
Mie goreng is coming.
MAN #5:
I've lived all over the world,
and I've never had anything
that tastes like this.
Two rendang, one satay,
one mie tahu.
WOMAN #2: We're really lucky
to be this little town
and have this
unique type of food.
FIERI: And the folks of Ashland
have this couple to thank,
Leslie Caplan and
Birong Hutabarat...
Babe, how long
for ayam bakar?
...who are bringing the flavors
of Birong's native Indonesia
to the heart of Oregon.
I came here to go
to college.
I had already lived in
Indonesia for eight years,
and then people were like,
"You've gotta meet Birong.
He's Indonesian."
Just like
"Days of our Indonesia."
I know.
How would you describe
an Indonesian restaurant?
Using the local spices you
can't find in the other region.
So it really is
the spice island.
It is.
FIERI:
And those spices are definitely
packing a punch in this
beefed-up flavor bomb.
Rendang for Jamie.
MAN #6: This is coconut curry,
and it's cooked
for so long, it literally
melts in your mouth.
Rendang.
Probably the most famous
dish in Indonesia.
Well, let's start going.
Coconut milk, galangal.
It's like ginger light.
Ginger light,
but it has kind of --
-A little more citrus?
-Yeah, more citrus.
This is a mix of cardamom,
coriander, and cumin.
-The three C.
-Cloves, turmeric.
Beautiful color and
flavor from that.
Shallot, raw sugar,
bay leaf, ginger.
Whole bunch of allspice.
Salt, garlic, cinnamon,
lemongrass,
our Indonesian chili.
Oh, it's going.
Go all the way
to coconut milk.
All the spices.
-Everybody in the bowl.
But what type of
meat are we using?
-We use chuck.
-A lot of great flavor.
Not the most tender.
So, how long's the chuck
gonna cook down
in this super fortified,
extra-flavored coconut milk?
Three to
three and a half hours.
I like it.
Ren-dang.
-Ren-dahng.
-Rendang.
Get your rendang right.
Now, what are we
gonna serve this with?
Coconut turmeric rice with
a garnish of a cucumber.
If people were to say
that the hamburger
was the dish of
the United States,
this would be
the dish of Indonesia.
Very true.
I should be able
to close my eyes
and teleport
to Indonesia.
-Yes.
-Okay.
[ Fork clangs ]
I don't even need
a passport.
♪♪
I've never had
that before.
One minute, I'm over
here in the lemongrass.
The next minute, I'm
over here in the spice.
Then I'm over here
with coconut milk.
If you love Indian food,
it's not that.
If you love Thai food,
But if you put Indian food
and Thai food together...
-Thai food together.
-...that's what you get.
It's tender.
It's tons of flavor.
It's a little bit of heat,
it's a little bit of sweet,
the touch of ginger.
It's delicious.
-Thank you, sir.
-Here's your rendang.
MAN #7:
It's got this rich flavor.
It just fills all
the good spaces.
That meat is
the most tender beef
you will ever eat, just awesome.
Funny enough, we
have Ferndale people
that I grew up with
now living in Ashland.
He comes here every week.
It's a funky
little place.
I have a question
for you, Guy.
When you were a little kid,
you might not remember this,
your mother put
a sign on your back.
Yeah, thanks, Jack.
It's been really nice
having the Allmans
here on the show.
Mie goreng for Thomas.
Were you a cook
back in Indonesia?
No, I went home for two years
and just find families...
WOMAN #3:
He goes back every year
and buys new spices
and brings them back.
And he'll come back
with recipes.
SERVER: Opor.
WOMAN #4: I'm having an opor.
I love the creamy
curry sauce that
has just that hint
of spice in it.
The chicken is soft,
moist, rich in flavor.
We're gonna make opor.
This is mild curry
with candlenut.
FIERI: Candlenut.
Is it a macadamian?
-No.
-Can you eat it?
You have to cook 'em
before you eat 'em.
Ah, so what is the dish?
It's called what, o--?
-Opor.
-Opor?
Yes, we put cumin,
coriander,
shallot, salt, sugar,
garlic, ginger.
Galangal.
White pepper,
toasted candlenut,
turmeric, a little bit
of water, and then...
Little bit of oil.
And we're gonna
cook this paste out.
Yes, we sauté it for
three, four minute.
And then we will
put all the spices...
-There you go.
-...into the coconut milk.
Lemongrass.
Indonesian lime leaf.
Very similar to the
Sri Lanka lime leaf.
-And bay leaf.
-Okay.
Then in
with the chicken thighs?
Yes.
We're gonna serve 'em
with organic veggies.
[ Cellphone rings ]
Hang on, I'm sorry,
hang on.
My mom.
Hello, Mother.
-Hi, Guy.
-Listen, I took your advice.
I don't always take
all the advice
you give me as I should,
but I will tell you,
pretty ridiculous.
It's the bomb, right?
I told you.
It's the bomb.
So, I wish I were there.
Have a great time.
-Love you, Mom.
-Bye.
Interrupted by my mother
when I'm getting
ready to eat.
♪♪
You know how some
people say
they don't like dark meat
on chicken?
This right here will
melt in your mouth.
It's capital-T tender.
There's a lot of depth
in this.
And the fresh, local veggies
with bite, with crunch.
It's pretty amazing.
-Thank you.
♪♪
It's so good.
The chicken is juicy,
it's moist.
I have never had a dish
like this before.
It's absolutely unique.
MAN #8: I tell my friends,
"You guys should go to Blue Toba
because it's like nothing
you've ever had."
Schwarzenegger stole
the line from me,
but I'll be back.
-We be here.
"I'll be back."
"We be here."
[ Laughter ]
So, was this a great
road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints to
find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Drivers,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
♪ Fish heads, fish heads ♪
♪ Roly-poly fish heads ♪
Sorry.
-I love it.
There are gonna be so many
shrimps without heads.