Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
That --
...get ready for
all kinds of home cookin'.
That's so good.
'Cause at these spots...
[ Groans ]
...mom's in the house.
This is where the magic happens,
ladies and gentlemen.
We've got legit Latin
in Mesa, Arizona...
You got me at hello.
...Caribbean classics
in Columbus, Ohio.
Wow.
Plus, in Boulder, Colorado...
I like the way she rolls.
...Chinese street food
that's out of this world.
Kryptonite.
I am weak in its power.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
I'm here in beautiful
Mesa, Arizona,
about 20 minutes east
of Downtown Phoenix,
to check out a joint
that's all about family.
Oh, they got brothers
and sisters,
nieces and nephews, mom and dad.
Everybody's working here.
And what are they making?
They're making some
Latin-American comfort food.
I'd love to put some of that
on my mesa -- or my table.
This is Republica Empanada.
♪♪
Salmon Torta!
When I have people
come out of town,
they say "where should I eat"?
It's here.
Two Capitán Empanadas.
Real deal?
This is the real deal.
Pernil Torta.
Come in with an empty stomach --
leave with a full heart.
FIERI:
'Cause for the Meraz clan,
this is truly a family affair.
Led by matriarch Jinette,
a former school-bus driver,
whose love of cooking
inspired this joint.
So, you were retired?
Oh, yes. I'm still full of pep
and vinegar, I tell you.
Whoo-ooh! Whoo-oop-oop-oop
oop-oop-oop!
I love this family.
Every time I walk in here,
I'm greeted with a smile
and great food.
MERAZ:
Cubana Empanada.
The Cubana is excellent.
It combines ham and cheese,
and it's very, very flavorful.
MERAZ: We're gonna start
preparing the pernil, so...
And what does pernil mean?
Pernil means pork.
Okay.
You put mustard, garlic...
-A lot of it.
-Comino. Salt.
Black pepper.
Oregano. Parsley.
Bay leaves. Wine.
In there, or in you?
[ Chuckles ] Both.
[ Laughs ]
Onions.
We cover this and put it
in the walk-in over night.
We add water.
How long are we
gonna cook it for?
4 to 5 hours.
What is that over there?
Where?
Oh, nothing.
[ Laughs ]
And then
we're gonna shred it.
And that's gonna be the
beginning of this empanada?
Exactly. What we're gonna
make is a Cubana.
A Cuban sandwich.
You got me at hello.
To bring out the flavors,
I like to...
So a little garlic
and some onion?
And a little oregano.
And then the pork.
This...
The Empanada 9000.
Yeah.
You put
the empanada dough in...
Spoon the mix
onto the disk.
Ham. Mozzarella.
Mozzarella.
And pepino.
Pickles.
What you call this?
Ta-da!
Whoo-hoo!
Look at that!
Okay, let's fry them.
Grease them and you fry them.
And how long?
2 or 3 minutes.
Here's the empanada.
♪♪
It's hot? [ Laughs ]
It's delicious.
The pickle is, of course,
the thing
that you're gonna pick up
right off the bat.
The empanada's
light and flaky.
The right mixture
of the pork and the ham.
A little bit of cheese.
Not too much.
Mm-hmm.
The salsa adds the acid.
That's fantastic.
SERVER: Two Cubana Empanadas?
I just like the different
textures that it has.
It's crunchy on the outside.
MAN: I open it up
just to look at it
because I'm so
passionate about it.
It really is that good.
MAN 2: I really like
this restaurant
because of the
international flavors
incorporated in their dishes.
WOMAN: It's a fusion of so many
different Latino cultures
that really is all embodied
in the food that they have here.
MERAZ: Arroz Con Pollo?
I have had their Arroz
Con Pollo many, many times.
WOMAN 2:
The flavors are amazing.
The salty, the sweet
of the peas, the avocado.
MAN: Big chunks of chicken
inside of rice.
It just tastes wonderful.
Okay, so Arroz Con Pollo.
Rice with chicken.
Very famous dish.
We're gonna start making
our Colt 45 Salsa.
The Colt 45.
Why do I call it that?
Because it has
all the ingredients.
It's "loaded," see?
You're crazy.
[ Laughs ]
So, we're gonna
put bell pepper.
Carrots. Onion.
Celery.
Cilantro.
A whole bunch of it.
Black pepper.
Salt. Cumin. And...
Oregano!
Oregano.
That's your middle name.
Yes.
Tomatoes. And water.
This is gonna boil
like an hour.
We'll immersion blender.
And then we'll make the chicken
for the Arroz Con Pollo.
Yes.
Okay.
And then we're gonna
put bay leaves.
Salt. Whole onion.
And a bunch of water.
And that cooks
for like 2 hours.
Once we're done shredding
the chicken, what do we do?
We're gonna make
Republica Chicken.
Okay. The onions.
Garlic.
Ga-a-arlic.
Yeah. What was that move?
[ Laughs ]
Bell peppers.
Cumin. Oregano.
Black pepper.
A little bit of peppercino.
Red chili flake.
Shredded chicken.
Achiote.
The annatto seed.
Beautiful color
we'll get out of that.
And then some of the 45.
That's the key.
And some cilantro?
Yeah.
Now we make
the rice part of it.
Yes. A little bit of oil.
Onions. Minced garlic.
This here is carrots,
onions, bell pepper...
Kinda like mirepoix,
right? Olives?
Olives and capers.
Add the chicken.
Next is rice.
Achiote. Cilantro.
And the peas.
See how beautiful it looks?
It think it's gorgeous.
Plate like this.
And turn it.
Garnish with
with aguacate.
Avocado. Tomato.
Potato chips?
Chips.
And cabbage.
Voila!
Look at that.
♪♪
The chicken's got
phenomenal flavor.
♪♪
Mmm. The carrots,
the capers, the olives?
The achiote.
The beautiful color.
Everything cooked down.
The Colt 45 sauce...
You get the sweet.
You get a little
bit of the heat.
Mmm. That's so good.
Arroz Con Pollo!
It's a party in your palate.
I'm from Costa Rica.
Arroz Con Pollo?
That's as good as you're
gonna find it at home?
Yes.
Empanada Platter!
Every time you come in here,
it's a wonderful experience.
I don't know who
could finish all that.
I don't know. You?
I'll be asleep.
[ Laughs ]
Great job, girl.
You're gonna love this place.
FIERI:
Up next in Boulder, Colorado.
This is the best fast Asian food
I've probably seen in 10 years.
And when you meet Ma Ma...
I mean, she makes that
look like child's play.
...you'll know why her
specialties are so darn good.
Look at those.
They're gorgeous.
Wala.
No wala. Voila.
Voi.
Wa.
Vwa.
Hmph. Va.
♪♪
So, I'm right off
of Pearl Street,
about a block away
from Pearl Street Mall.
I know that sounds confusing.
When you're in Boulder,
Colorado, ask anybody --
they'll tell you
how to get here.
Anyhow, you'll love this place.
Tons of shops. All kinds
of restaurants -- Mexican.
Italian. German.
Nepalese. You name it.
But I'm here to check out
one joint in particular.
It's got super
yummy street food.
The one and only Zoe Ma Ma.
♪♪
Potstickers ready.
It's like a little
China in Boulder.
You got the main dish, girl.
I know.
FIERI:
This is traditional.
I mean, this is authentic.
This is it.
FIERI: It's straight out of
Ma Ma's cookbook.
Ma Ma is a very special person.
She's the life of the place.
She's the heart of the food.
FIERI: And her love of cooking
led Anne Zoe
to come out of her retirement
and join her son Edwin
in this personal adventure.
This is a place that's making
what Mom wants to make,
how Mom wants to make it.
Yes.
And where's your family
originally from?
My mom's from Taiwan --
was born in Taiwan,
but my father's
from Northern China.
How do we explain the food?
Home-style Taiwanese and Chinese
street-and-home-style.
What are we gonna make today?
My mom's homemade Steamy Bun.
I've had steamy buns
from all over the nation.
These are one of the best.
It's full of meat.
Very pronounced flavor.
We start?
Yeah, please.
Yeast. Water.
Salt. Sugar.
The flour.
Organic, high gluten. Okay.
Oil.
And do you have to drag
your mom out of here?
Yeah.
She works way too much.
So, we'll let that rest.
30 to 40.
30 to 40 minutes.
And in the meantime,
we'll make the filling?
Yeah.
So, everything is
done with induction?
Yes.
Because it's more
comfortable for my mom.
Otherwise it'd be
a really hot kitchen.
I didn't want that for her.
Shh on all
the super-son stuff, okay?
My mom's watching.
[ Laughs ]
You know what I'm gonna
have to go through?
The oil. Onion.
The green onions.
The whites of the green onion.
I like the whites
of the green onions.
Ground pork.
Cooking wine.
Salt. Sugar.
"Five-spicy" powder.
Five-spicy powder.
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
And ginger. Okay.
Sweet paste.
Sweet-bean paste.
And celery.
Right at the end
for a little crunch.
Okay, I like this.
♪♪
You could serve
that in anything.
Hurry up and make these
before I eat all the filling.
Okay.
She's gonna be
portioning them.
She didn't have
to measure it twice.
This is where the magic happens,
ladies and gentlemen.
Rolling it. Turning it.
Twisting it.
I always think of that
as a really accomplished DJ.
Yeah, wicky-wicky wick.
I mean, she makes that
look like child's play.
This is gonna go right into
looking like a soup dumpling.
Bigger.
Ah!
Look at those! They're gorgeous!
How long will this steam?
15 minutes.
15 minutes?
Yeah.
What's up with this one?
Want more?
I'm kidding.
I'm kidding. One's good.
What are the different
sauces I have here?
This is a crushed chili.
And then this is ginger onion.
And this is one of my favorites.
The Sichuan peppercorn.
♪♪
You okay?
[ Laughter ]
The bun's ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
This is light
and fluffy and tender.
Then this one's the...?
Chili paste.
Like sambal?
Yeah.
Kryptonite right there.
I am weak in its power.
[ Laughs ]
Want to one more?
Okay, sure.
Look at that.
♪♪
Oh, my gosh. Delicious.
Well done.
Thank you.
It's fluffy and flavorful.
The pork on the inside
is fantastic.
Little bit of spice.
It's all right?
Oh, thank you.
It's a really
great place to stop,
especially after a long
hike here in Boulder
which is what we
all love to do here.
It's a very small menu,
but it's really neat.
Look at what you're
offering. Potstickers.
SERVER:
Ma Ma's Chicken Soup Noodle.
You can come in and just
get something really fast,
like the Dan Dan Mian.
I usually order
the Dan Dan Mian.
It's my favorite.
Fantastic Sichuan Pork.
Now we're making Dan Dan.
So, the high-gluten flour again.
She's really
eyeballing this right now?
Generally, yeah.
Little bit more.
I like the way she rolls.
The salt.
So we're basically
making pasta at this point.
Yes.
An egg.
Water. The oil.
We let it rest
for about a half an hour.
Then we'll sheet it out.
Look at that!
That's as easy as it goes?
Okay.
Ready?
Yeah.
Now we're gonna make the topping
for the Dan Dan Noodle.
Yes.
Okay.
Okay, I start...
With an oil.
Mm-hmm.
Onion. Pork.
Cooking wine.
Cooking wine?
Soy sauce.
Ginger? Sugar?
Five-spicy powder.
Very similar to
the filling for the Bao,
but now the key
change will come?
We call it winter vegetable.
Basically it's like
a pickled vegetable.
That looks funky.
Chicken broth.
Sichuan.
Cook that a little bit.
The clay-pot funk is in there.
Yeah.
Okay.
Do the noodle.
Don't leave me unattended.
So,
we just cook the noodle.
Pickled daikon.
Sichuan peppercorn.
Cilantro.
Green onions.
And a little broth?
Just to give it
a little extra love.
♪♪
Okay?
[ Laughs ]
I really can't put it down.
I'm just gonna get it
closer to my face hole.
I'm glad she gives it
that little bit of broth
at the bottom.
And the key to it
is it's balanced.
I'm getting the ginger,
I'm getting the green
onion, the cilantro.
I mean, everything is
really fragrant right now
as it warmed up.
It's fresh. It's real.
It's balanced. I love it.
-Don Don Mian.
-It's delicious.
MAN: And the winter vegetables
in there just --
you get a little bit
of that vinegar flavor.
It's like the perfect mix
of pork and noodles.
FIERI:
This is the best fast Asian food
I've probably seen in 10 years.
This is killer.
I love coming here.
I always walk away
feeling satisfied.
You cook amazing.
And this combination,
this relationship, is amazing.
Any time you come to California,
you cook at my house.
Okay.
It's a deal.
You heard that.
Coming up...
A family-filled Jamaican joint
in Columbus, Ohio.
So, this is part restaurant,
part Ena's house, part hangout.
That's right.
Where island
favorites are fired up...
Look at that.
...by an unforgettable expert.
That's a lot of work
for one dish.
But you won't regret it
when you taste it.
I don't think
I'm gonna regret it.
♪♪
FIERI:
So, I'm here in the Linden
neighborhood of Columbus, Ohio.
Now, back in the day,
this is the major shopping area.
But as times change,
things change.
Well, that's actually
a good thing here
because it opened the door
to a type of food
you might not have found
in Columbus before.
This is Ena's Caribbean Kitchen.
♪♪
Grilled Lamb.
This is
authentic Jamaican food.
Maybe better than something
you can get in Jamaica.
Snapper Filet.
Plantains and cabbage.
Everything seems to
be made from scratch.
Some of the best home
cookin' in Columbus.
FIERI: All from the kitchen
of Ena Hayles...
Oxtail. Rice and peas and grits.
FIERI: ...who thrives
on feeing the masses.
Were you in the restaurant
business in Jamaica?
No. I didn't have it
in Jamaica.
But I did have it
at my house.
You had a Jamaican
restaurant at your house?
No. My kids bring their
friends to the house.
So they're saying,
"Now, what'd you cook today?"
And they love it.
How many kids do you have?
Five.
Everybody work here?
Oh, yeah.
So this is part restaurant,
part Ena's house, part hangout.
That's right.
And it's where Ena's still
serving those island classics.
Jerked Chicken.
MAN: This Jerked Chicken.
It gives me that
flavor of Jamaica,
so I feel like I'm there.
It's juicy.
It's got a little bit of a kick
to it which is really nice.
What are we gonna make?
We're gonna make the rub
for Jerked Chicken.
Salt. Paprika.
Paprika?
Paprika.
I'm a Jamaican.
I didn't know.
[ Laughs ]
I'm really gonna say,
it's the first time
I'd even heard about this.
Pepper blend.
Garlic powder.
Onion powder.
Black pepper, white.
That's white pepper. You can't
say "black pepper, white."
That didn't make --
You're Jamaican.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
[ Laughs ]
Adobo. Pimento allspice.
I like the way
you do shout it out.
Cayenne pepper.
Now we're going to do
the wet rub for the chicken.
Garlic.
Scotch bonnet pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Onions. Thyme.
Red chilies.
House dry rub.
Which you can also
buy here, right?
That's right.
Shameless plug.
Soy sauce.
Wine?
What are you doing,
getting everybody drunk?
Oh, Lord, yes.
Liquid smoke.
Vinegar. And some browning.
Yeah, brown sauce.
Let it roll.
♪♪
Now we're gonna prep
our Jerked Chicken
with the dry rub,
the wet rub.
24 hours. What do you got
for me next?
Jerk sauce.
This is a lot of work
for one dish.
But you won't regret it
when you taste it.
I don't think
I'm gonna regret it.
Water. Browning.
Port wine.
You and the wine again.
Soy sauce.
Liquid smoke.
Onion. Garlic. Carrots.
A bunch of scotch bonnets.
[ Laughs ]
Garlic powder. Adobo.
Black pepper.
Breadcrumbs.
Jerk marinade. Dry rub.
That you make.
That I made.
Chicken seasoning.
Corn starch.
We call this tighten-it-up.
Tighten-it-up.
Bring to a boil.
Now we get to the chicken.
And are we grilling these,
or --
how are we cooking it
for the Jamaican --
Grill.
If you don't grill it,
you don't get that flavor.
We grill it first and then
finish it in the oven?
Yes.
Rice and peas.
Dried plantain.
Jerk sauce on the chicken.
♪♪
You get a little texture
from the grill on the outside.
You get that marinade.
A little bit of that heat,
a little bit of that salt,
a little bit of that garlic,
that scotch bonnet...
Yes.
...all the way down
in that chicken.
That's why only Jamaicans
can do jerked chicken.
Well, I'll tell you what this
non-Jamaican's doing
right now...
[ Laughs ]
Shoveling jerked chicken.
MAN:
Jerked Chicken is awesome.
It's spicy. It's tender.
Very flavorful.
It's very fresh.
I show up in Columbus, Ohio,
and who do I find?
I find my cousin Robby Price,
his buddy Doug.
So tell me about Jerked Chicken.
It has a fantastic spice.
I mean, I've always loved
Care-ibbean food.
Do you say Caribbean
or Care-ibbean?
Well, it depends.
Care-ibbean or Caribbean?
Caribbean.
WOMAN: Care-ibbean.
Aghh!
[ Laughter ]
Miss Ena, how do you say it?
Careibbean.
[ Laughter ]
That was both!
No matter what you call it,
one thing's for sure.
There's plenty to go
around at this joint.
I highly recommend you try
everything on her menu.
It's incredible.
I want to
finish eating this.
Mm-hmm.
We come back...
Mm-hmm?
...make another dish?
Okay.
Escabeche Fish.
It's just very flavorful.
It's very tender.
It's cooked just right.
See you in a minute.
♪♪
Welcome back. Hanging out in
Columbus, Ohio, at Miss Ena's.
Miss Ena always has a kind word,
always says hello to you.
Everything good?
MAN: It feels like stepping
out of Columbus, Ohio,
and flying to Jamaica.
What do we got next?
Red Snapper. Escabeche.
What does the escabeche
part mean?
Sauce.
'Cause everything here,
by the way, is a sauce.
Sauce.
We got a marinade.
We got a sauce.
We got a sauce
for the marinade sauce.
Escabeche Red Snapper.
The Escabeche Red Snapper
is like right out of the ocean.
It melts in your mouth,
and you taste all of the spices.
Beautiful red snapper.
The scales
have been taken off.
Cut through the skin.
And we're gonna put a dry rub.
Yes. Garlic powder.
Onion powder.
Salt.
Black pepper. Allspice.
Cayenne pepper.
Adobo. Paprika.
Mix this up.
Get it all over the fish.
Into the slice.
Under the cavity.
And how long's it gonna
sit with the dry rub?
This don't have to sit
because the fish is fresh.
While that is frying,
we're going to make
the escabeche sauce.
We got to go fast!
Okay, escabeche sauce!
Go!
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Water.
Vinegar. Carrots.
Onion.
Scotch bonnet pepper.
Come on.
Thyme. Sugar. Salt.
And the allspice berry.
Love that allspice berry.
Now, how long are you
gonna let that cook?
For about 10,
15 minutes, boil it.
Fish is fried.
Let's see it.
Escabeche sauce.
Look at that.
♪♪
Anybody that doesn't like fish,
come down and give them this.
The fish is really tender.
Great spice rub to it.
But it's the vinegar...
it's the escabeche sauce...
♪♪
that kills it.
Wow. Nicely done.
Thank you.
MAN: The sauce is vinegary,
and it's got scotch
bonnet peppers
which kick up the spices a lot.
-Red Snapper.
-Very juicy.
Very good.
-Curry Goat.
-The food is just dynamic.
I've traveled to Jamaica,
and I think this is better.
You really feel that effort
and love was put into each meal.
FIERI:
When you have a restaurant
that's this popular,
people are happy
to live close to it.
We get customers
from all over Columbus.
You got one all the way
from California.
Yes, I do sure.
[ Laughs ]
Great job.
So, that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
for some of the joints we visit,
well, go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
Okay. Don't look
at the camera.
Oh.
Remember, you're not supposed
to look at the camera.
You're just dying to look
at the camera. Just do it.
Ready? 1, 2, 3.
Look at the camera!
[ Laughs ]
That's a bucket list!
That's right.
Okay!