Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Imitates siren ]
We're digging in
to California cookin'...
Come on!
My man!
...served up
with the unexpected.
This is a first.
Like Southern in San Fran...
Fixins.
...and a surprising pie
in Sacramento...
Can't beat it.
...along with a French twist.
This guy's nuts.
Plus, a Taste of Italy
in Carmel...
Look at this.
...fresh Monterey seafood...
Mmm.
...scratch breakfast
in North Cal...
That is awesome.
...and an Oakland
Flavortown fiesta.
For people right now that are
saying, "I wish I was there,"
I'm doing this for you.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, you know that when
you're enjoying a meal
it's not just the food
you're eating,
it's the experience
you're having.
You want a real-deal
pizza experience,
you're in a pizza parlor.
You want to have sausage
and beer, you're in a hofbrau.
You're looking
for some authentic,
real-deal Mexican food,
where do you find yourself?
How about an open market?
So I'm here in Oakland,
California, in Old Oakland,
to check out the real deal.
This is Cosecha.
♪♪
Here you go,
pico de gallo.
WOMAN: I've been to, like, every
type of Mexican restaurant,
and, by far,
Cosecha's the best.
Four tacos all day?
MAN:
Dominica is truly the nicest,
most engaging chef in Oakland
that I know of.
FIERI: And Dominica Rice earned
those chops working in kitchens
from San Fran to Manhattan
to Mexico City...
I got it, I got it.
...before setting up shop
in a nearly vacant
marketplace in 2011.
When people started to realize
how good her food was,
how authentic it was,
she really filled this place up.
A revival happened,
which was great.
What kind
of Mexican restaurant is it?
We're doing
Oakland Mexican food.
This type of cooking
has always been in California.
But it's her own twist
on the taco
that's got folks
filling this joint.
Fish tacos, shrimp tacos,
pork belly tacos.
We have two orders
of pork belly.
Amazing, juicy,
succulent, nom nom,
pork belly tacos.
Yeah!
Get me into it.
This is skin-on pork belly.
Where'd you get all
the earthenware?
Half of them come in from Mexico
that we have custom made for us,
and then the other half
comes in from Spain.
Gorgeous.
Salt it, and that's it?
That's it.
And we let that marinate
overnight.
We're gonna start
to prepare the achiote paste
for the pork belly.
Whole garlic, kosher salt.
So, you got a nice
little paste out of that.
Yes.
And then we just add the achiote
paste, which is annatto seed.
Beautiful red color.
And we're breaking this up.
We're ready to add
the citrus.
Oh, gracias.
I'll load the cannon.
Lemon and lime and
a little bit of orange juice.
So, take a little bit
of the achiote paste.
And you're doing everything
authentic.
It's the whole enchilada,
no pun intended.
[ Chuckles ]
So, we're gonna add --
The Mexican mirepoix of
jalapeños, onions, and garlic.
Garlic, exactly.
Here we go.
Cerveza.
-Okay.
Covered?
Yep.
And place it into the oven
at 350
for an hour
and 45 minutes.
So, we're making
the pickled red onions
that we use on a lot
of our tacos.
Kosher salt, jalapeños,
chile de árbol,
the Mexican
piloncillo sugar.
Piloncillo sugar?
So, this is cooked-down
sugarcane juice.
So it has all the molasses.
Everything's together.
Bay Leaves.
-Hibiscus?
Yeah.
The jamaica flower.
Two cinnamon sticks.
We're gonna add some water
to that,
and then we're gonna add
red wine vinegar.
And I let that simmer
for about 10 to 15 minutes.
I'll be over here.
Whoo! Press it down
with the weights,
and then let it sit for,
like, an hour and a half.
Love it.
Then we've chilled
our pork belly --
And then I'll check the onions
that we've made.
-Yes. Yes, yes, yes.
-That's important.
So, I'm gonna slice
off a few portions.
Those will be fine.
A little acid bite there.
Then we salt them up.
-Sear 'em off.
-Yeah.
That's, like, the most
perfect hand-made tortilla.
They're made to order,
so the skin-on pork belly
I love, because it has that
little bit
of that chicharrón crunch.
And we put a little bit
of the tomatillo salsa.
Pickled onion.
You've outweighed the tortilla
5:1 with the pork.
Fresh sliced jalapeño,
and then a little cilantro.
A little sprinkle of salt
and a little bit of lime.
Ready to roll.
♪♪
The skin is so thin
in that part of the belly
it starts to crunch up
with a little bit
of its own fat.
It's quintessential
that you have the pickled onion
inside of there.
It's every aspect --
the squeeze of the lemon,
the touch of the salt.
For people
right now that are saying,
"I wish I was there,"
I'm doing this for you.
How did our bite taste?
Tastes fantastic.
Two pork bellies up on 19.
These tacos are kind of
an emotional experience for me.
MAN: Just perfectly crispy
pieces of pork belly --
nice contrast
with the red onion.
Makes you feel like you're
no longer in the Bay area.
FIERI: You eat out
of the little pottery dishes,
and you're thinking,
"I'm in a Mexican market."
Doesn't it feel like it?
-Yeah, for sure.
MAN: You can actually
smell the tortillas
from about a block away,
so it's always
luring you over here.
-But that's not all your tricks.
-No.
We have more.
-I heard you got more.
-Carne Adovada?
Sí.
It's a pork shoulder.
I salt this the night before,
and we tied it up.
So, trussed it
so it doesn't fall apart.
We're gonna be adding
toasted and ground cumin.
-Old-school methods.
-Maximum flavor.
And then we have a little bit
of the Spanish paprika --
smoked pimenton -- tomatoes,
and then bay leaves,
some onion,
and garlic.
Cerveza...
that we love so much.
And some jalapeño, as well.
Ready for the oven.
Here we go.
-How long are we gonna cook off?
For about two and a half hours
at 350.
Okay.
What are we into now?
We're making guajillo salsa.
So guajillo, chile de árbol,
and garlic?
And letting it steep
for five minutes.
Okay. I'm gonna puree
the guajillo chilies.
Add in the chicken broth.
Add a little bit of salt.
Strain the guajillo chili.
Okay.
This is one of the mother
sauces for Mexican cuisine.
Sauté it with some aromatics
and a little bit of olive oil.
Bay leaves, onion,
and garlic.
We're gonna add in
the cumin
and the Mexican oregano.
-Oh, yeah.
It's very different
than the Italian oregano.
We're adding the guajillo.
Let this simmer
for about 10, 15 minutes.
A little kosher salt,
and it's ready to go.
This is the Carne Adovada,
ready to serve.
She just threw away
the dental floss of Flavortown.
Gonna get a little
of chili sauce on top of this.
Okay.
Get it.
You have just a little bit
of cilantro.
And some homemade tortillas.
I don't know
if I should eat it
or take a picture
with it.
♪♪
You have good tortilla
technique, so that's important.
I've got a good hold.
Todo bien?
I feel like
I need my passport.
It's a simple Mexican dish.
It's not over-the-top.
It's pork roast,
guajillo, chile de árbol,
simple rice and beans,
great handmade tortillas.
Everything's just what it is
in the great form.
That's the difference.
-Carne Adovada?
-It's so tender --
just simply paired with rice
and beans and a tortilla.
It's all you need.
-Like, everything is perfect.
-Every detail.
But it remains,
nevertheless, fully accessible.
That's what I want my shirt
to say!
MAN: You're gonna leave with one
of the best food experiences
you've ever had.
And if you've ever been
to a Mexican market,
you understand the kinetic
energy that's going on.
It just has that feeling.
-Thank you.
And the food is fantastic.
-Thank you. Yay!
-Outstanding.
FIERI: Comin' up in
Carmel-by-the-Sea...
Calm down, G.
You're dancin'.
...colorful
East Coast Italian...
It's a bada, no bing.
...swimmin' in
real-deal flavor.
Now I'm done.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in this cool little town
called Carmel-by-the-Sea,
California.
Great restaurants,
lots of cool little shops,
and I'm hanging out
with my buddy here,
G. Garvin.
Now, G., I know
what you're wanting.
You're saying, "Get me some
really good barbecue,
some sweet potatoes --"
Oh! No barbecue.
Then how about Italian?
This is Little Napoli.
Ravioli going down
with the Arrabbiata sauce.
WOMAN: It's so good.
And I just know
that I'm getting
something authentic.
PèPE:
Chicken parmigiana, here we go.
It just embraces everything
that Italian life
is supposed to be.
FIERI: That's because since
1989, owner and chef Rich Pèpe
has been serving up
family recipes
you don't usually see
outside the boot.
With all my grandparents
coming from Southern Italy,
that's where
we really focus.
That's what I grew up with.
And also, being from
New Jersey, you know,
if you don't put good food
on the table,
somebody's gonna get hurt.
Truly.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
PèPE:
Cannelloni tricolore, pick up.
Love the cannelloni.
It's such a surprise
when it arrives.
It has red, white, and green
like the Italian flag.
Tricolore.
Three colors, my brother.
Come on!
My man.
So, how we starting
this off?
Working the stuffing
right now?
Yes, sir.
Hit it.
Pèppoli extra virgin
olive oil,
onions, zucchini,
yellow squash, and mushrooms.
Fresh ground pepper
over the top.
Little bit of kosher salt.
Just sweating it a bit.
Just sweating it a bit
'cause it will cook later on
when we make
the cannelloni roll.
Chicken coming in.
This is grilled chicken.
Okay.
Just a little parsley
at the end just to fold.
Basically, that's done.
Now we're gonna make
the pesto sauce.
Got it.
Garlic.
Fresh basil.
A lot of it.
Olive oil.
♪♪
Parmigiano-reggiano.
Blend it just
for a couple of seconds.
I don't want to heat
that cheese up at all.
I like you leave a little
texture to it. Okay.
Let me get after that
for you, boss.
[ Chuckles ]
Nice, G.
Hey, man.
I'm over here helping.
G.'s digging
in the back side.
Hey, I'm a guest
on the show, baby.
I get to do what I want to do.
Okay. Now we'll fold in
a little heavy cream.
Now you make your own pasta,
as well.
We do.
Wow.
Just a traditional...
semolina and egg pasta.
Boil it off,
little salt water.
So, this is our
pre-boiled sheet.
Pipe in the ricotta
and parmesan and egg
filling cheese.
Bada bing.
Did we just get
a "bada bing"?
You got
a little bada bing.
Bada who?
A little shout out for Jersey.
What can I say?
Now we can take
our filling.
We're gonna lay it
across.
Now we are just gonna
fold it over,
making like a big burrito.
We're gonna go
into the skillet
with a little bit of water
and we're gonna steam it up.
Two, three minutes.
Two or three minutes.
Just a bada, no bing.
Then we're gonna plate
this puppy up.
The marinara.
Pesto cream sauce.
And the Alfredo.
Shaved
reggiano parmigiano.
Roasted pine nuts.
Pea shoots.
I got to tell you.
Just like the Italian flag.
It is gorgeous.
♪♪
We'll meet in the middle
like "Lady and the Tramp."
Whoa.
[ Chuckles ]
Calm down, G.
You're dancing.
Man.
Here we go.
Get it out.
Three words.
Forget about it.
Ooh.
That's the best compliment
you can get.
To me,
one of the keys to this
that I'm really digging
is the simplicity.
You execute the pasta perfectly,
you make your own sauces.
But what makes the dish
so great
is with so many flavors
on the plate,
there's no reason to make it
any more complex.
Just let the simplicity of it
shine through.
And that's really
what I enjoy the most.
Man, it all works well together.
It's phenomenal.
Nice job, Pèpe.
Thank you.
Excellent.
Tricolore cannelloni.
Everything inside's very warm
and fresh and delicious.
Everything tastes fabulous
from the very beginning
until the very end.
Cioppino rosso.
Okay.
Next up, what do we got?
We're coming in now
with the cioppino rosso.
This is bouillabaisse
gone wild.
We're gonna make the sauce
and we're gonna use the shells.
So I'm really just going
to just rub some paste
through the shells
and just put them in the oven
for about 15 minutes
just to get them warmed up.
350 degrees?
Yeah, maybe 350.
Great.
In a warm stock pot,
extra virgin olive oil.
Some red onion.
Chopped garlic.
Lots of it.
Chopped celery.
Carrots.
Saffron threads.
Nice.
Color and flavor.
♪♪
All right, Chef.
You can see we've just kind
of caramelized the shells a bit,
roasted the tomato paste
on there.
Deglaze
with some white wine.
Come in
with some ground tomatoes.
Crushed red pepper.
[ Whistles ]
Oregano.
Fair amount of salt.
How long
do you let it cook for?
15, 20 minutes.
Pull it, strain it.
And we use the immersion blender
on it.
Cioppino sauce is done.
Now we're putting it
together.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Shallot.
Manila clams.
Black mussels.
Calamari.
White prawns.
Scallops.
Calamari tentacles.
Crab claw.
Baby shrimp.
Stir it up a little bit.
Deglaze with white wine,
Chardonnay.
Reduce it down.
Cioppino sauce
that we made earlier.
And as soon as that's hot
and those clams open,
we're good to go.
We're done.
Cover it up.
2, 3, 4 minutes,
you're finished.
Got it.
Fresh pasta going down
in the boiling water.
Let's take a look
at our cioppino.
Mmm, it's gorgeous.
Pasta coming out
of the water.
Oh!
Look at that.
A little sauce
over the top.
And now we are gonna go in
with our seafood.
Look at this.
That's like grandma
used to make.
Fresh parsley over the top.
Little chili oil
over the top.
Ohh.
I don't want to hurt you.
I don't want to hurt you now.
Cioppino rosso.
You make the pasta,
you make the sauce,
you roast the shells,
you live in the house
of Pèpeville.
♪♪
Oh, the sauce is bananas.
Nice spice to it.
Pasta's not overcooked.
This is spicy, just the right
amount of heat.
It's gorgeous.
Oh, it's spot-on.
I make cioppino.
It's one of my favorite
personal dishes.
This is outstanding.
Oh, yeah.
That means a lot.
Thank you.
Mmm.
Okay.
Now I'm done.
♪♪
Cioppino rosso.
Andiamo.
WOMAN: It makes you feel like
you're in the Italian coast
with fresh seafood that
just jumps out of the water.
MAN:
It's pretty much the only place
that we can come and get it
where it's very similar
to how we make it at home.
Pèpe knows exactly
what he's doing.
Little bit of shallots.
What you've done,
how you're doing it,
your love
of the Italian culture,
and you really exude that.
Wonderful.
Very nice to meet you,
Chef.
♪♪
Up next, we're headed up
the road to Monterey.
Crazy.
And here, the seafood
is a local jewel...
I'm an abalone junkie.
...and a royal favorite.
Dungeness crab, to me,
is the king of the sea.
♪♪
I'm here
in Monterey, California,
on Municipal Wharf 2.
Now, this is the working wharf.
There's a tourist wharf
on that side.
But this is where the boats
really come in.
I mean, you got an abalone farm
down there,
you got a fish market,
you name it.
And you need a place
for the wharf workers to eat.
And that's right here
at this joint,
LouLou's Griddle in the Middle.
♪♪
This is really good food.
Fish tacos.
Oh, great.
It's my favorite place to come.
It's almost like dancing
in the aisles.
It's time to party.
FIERI:
A party that started in 2001
when Loulou Garrett
bought the joint.
And 10 years later, her business
partner, Gigi Davis,
jumped ship from corporate life
to join the fun.
This is now my office,
which I feel
incredibly grateful for.
Really stressful.
I don't know.
You must have a real good
therapy plan here.
This super-chill spot used to be
a bait shop back in '48.
And it's still keeping up
that fresh-catch tradition.
Halibut over
mixed baby greens.
...hauling in one
of my favorites, abalone.
Fresh is the best.
And it's actually farmed and
grown right here in the bay.
Crazy.
These bad boys are amazing.
They're not like calamari.
They're not like clams.
They're like something
you've never had before.
A little more buttery
than calamari.
Yeah, more buttery.
Fattier than calamari.
GARRETT: Abalone sliders.
They are so delicate
and flavorful
and probably the perfect slider.
♪♪
I'm an abalone junkie.
Abalone is the jewel
of the Pacific North coast.
It is.
Okay, get after it.
Okay.
We're gonna make the dredge
for the abalone sliders.
Flour, white pepper.
Okay.
Garlic salt.
Got it.
All Seasoned salt.
Cayenne. Paprika.
That's it. Simple.
Don't be afraid
that she put that much Cayenne
in there.
It's not
super-spicy Cayenne.
No.
It's not gonna hurt you.
Let's do it.
Aren't they beautiful?
Yep, right there.
Done.
Wow, this is fresh.
Yes.
Okay, here we go.
So, we finish the little finish
of the tenderizing.
Not so much that
you broke all the flesh
'cause you want it
to have its texture.
Take those out. We're gonna
just dredge them up.
Great.
Got our pan heating here.
I'm gonna put the buns down
'cause it's gonna cook super
quick, less than a minute.
High heat.
Little clarified butter
there.
Just enough to warm them up
and put a crust on them.
Pretty much.
This is like calamari
gone wild.
You do not want
to overcook them.
♪♪
We're gonna make the aioli.
I'll do the mayo.
Okay.
Go 'cause I don't want
that abalone to overcook.
Lime juice.
Mayo, lime juice, check.
We have an olive oil that's been
infused with lemongrass.
Very nice.
Fresh cilantro.
Salt, pepper.
Lime zest.
Check!
Check on those abalones.
Get it good.
That enough?
That's enough.
Abalone slider.
Put a little slaw
on there.
That's a little radish,
cilantro.
Got that.
Fruit slaw.
♪♪
It's so tender.
Great abalone flavor.
Not too much spice.
The bun fits it well.
I mean, I love any great
sourdough bun like this.
♪♪
Slaw complements it.
All the bright, fresh flavors
with the crunch --
it's fantastic.
Great.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Mmm!
♪♪
That's good abalone.
The spices are blended
perfectly together.
How do you explain
the seafood
that you get here
at LouLou's?
It's so fresh.
MAN: And the boat pulls up
right to the back
of the restaurant.
You watch it get unloaded.
You can't beat that.
FIERI: And they're pulling in
this hands-on favorite.
GARRETT: Crab feast.
When crab season comes around,
everybody gets excited
because we know we're gonna have
a good meal that night.
From November 2nd
to right around June...
GARRETT: Yep.
...you can get fresh
dungeness crab.
And dungeness crab, to me,
is the king of the sea.
So how do you do yours?
Simple.
Sea salt.
Bay leaves.
Couple lemons.
We're just gonna drop
the whole lemon in there.
Garlic. That's it.
So a simple seasoning
to it,
not too much stealing
from the flavor.
Yep.
Look at that.
Upside-down.
Buh-bye.
Wait till you see how vibrant
orange it's gonna turn.
Okay. How long you gonna
have it down?
About 15, 20 minutes.
Ready?
Bring it.
You take the shell,
clean out the mustard,
and do all that.
Yes.
Unless they ask for it.
Unless they want the yum-yum.
They might.
♪♪
We just put that top shell
on just to...
Just 'cause
you want to make --
Just 'cause it's beautiful.
Corn. Potato.
Parsley. Butter.
Lemon.
Now, at my house, I don't use
this fancy-dancy stuff.
I just get that fork right in
there, just rip it right open.
That's how I get after it.
Little bit of lemon.
♪♪
Crab.
[ Sighs ]
The natural flavor of the
dungeness crab is outrageous.
Sweet.
And it's buttery,
it's sweet, it's tender.
The key to this is...
you didn't mess with it.
No.
You just treat it
with respect.
Little respect.
Cook it the right way,
serve it hot.
More lemon.
Outrageous.
Creamy and buttery,
delicious.
Wouldn't mind getting messy
for this crab at all.
Fun joint and I can see
why you're so successful.
That boat-to-table attitude
is alive and well.
Awesome.
Thank you so much.
♪♪
FIERI: Comin' up on this
full hour of cruisin' Cali...
Oh-oh.
A Sacramento spot
blowing up the bánh mí...
Really, really good.
...and smokin' up the slaw.
You heard me --
Smoked slaw.
-We in Flavortown?
-Your GPS is workin'.
♪♪
I think by now,
most people are aware
that I'm from California
and very proud to be.
Now, when I hear there's a joint
close to the state capital,
here in Sacramento,
that's rockin' out
handmade gastropub food
and they get their name
from The Golden State
and the bear on its flag,
well, you know
I gotta check it out.
This is The Golden Bear.
-These tacos are ready to sell.
-I need a runner!
-Their food is top-notch.
-Plating up the tacos.
I'm having the chicken tacos.
I love 'em.
I got a juicy Lucy.
Great food, great friends.
It's all neighborhood, man.
That's what the attitude was?
-Local.
-Oh, yeah.
FIERI: Opened by a couple
of local guys...
Thanks for coming in.
...college buddies
Kimio Bazett...
Duck confit club.
...and Jon Modrow...
Enjoying your food, guys?
Always.
Where friends get together.
-For drinks and bar basics...
-Here you are, ladies.
FIERI: ...until they brought in
Chef Billy Zoellin...
Bacon Reuben!
...to turn
the bar menu on its ears.
Prosciutto-peach panini.
So, he just takes everything
and just does it the Billy way?
Oh, yeah.
Your basic Reuben.
No pastrami. It's all bacon.
Kind of crazy.
-Or a club sandwich.
-Bacon and duck?
Very rich,
but I love it real bad.
FIERI: And how about a pizza?
No sauce, no cheese.
Here comes the slaw.
It's my favorite item
on the menu.
It's our take on a classic
picnic sandwich,
you know, sausage and slaw.
Smoked slaw -- I've heard
about it. So what do you got?
All right, we start
with some hickory chips,
perf pan, ice, plastic wrap,
shredded savoy.
So, we don't want to cook
the cabbage.
Exactly.
We're just gonna throw some
flavor to it with the smoke.
Yeah. Put that on top
of our wood chips.
This is a first.
Cover it with tinfoil.
How long are we gonna
put it on to smoke?
4 minutes.
All right, so the slaw
is perfumed with smoke.
-Cabbage goes straight in.
-Okay.
House-made aioli,
whole-grain mustard,
apple cider vinegar, a little
bit of sugar, grated onion.
Now we just get
this good and mixed.
A little bit of salt.
Oh-ho-ho!
That changes my whole
attitude about slaw.
So, hold this cold?
Yep.
All right,
to make the sausage,
we're gonna start with some
freshly-chopped garlic,
chopped onion, fresh oregano,
fresh-chopped parsley.
Italian?
Of course.
Toasted ground fennel,
chili flakes,
a little red wine,
red wine vinegar.
A little bite.
A little salt.
Fresh-ground pepper.
Only way to go.
Dried oregano,
a little sugar.
There we go. Boom.
We're gonna whisk this up.
Okay.
So we got local,
fresh pork.
Can't beat it.
We'll get this
all good and mixed.
This is gonna rest up
for at least 24 hours.
Yes.
All right, so now we're
gonna work on the onions?
Yeah.
So, super-thin-sliced
red onions.
Yeah.
A real low temperature.
Hit it with some salt right off
the bat, draw out the moisture.
Exactly. It's been
about 20, 25 minutes.
So, our onions
break down real well.
I take a little balsamic,
reduce this down.
-Even more?
-Yeah.
And what are these
going for?
Red onion marmalade.
In a separate pan,
we're gonna make some caramel.
-Now that goes in?
-Yes.
We add that
into our onions.
I like it a lot.
Season this with
a little bit of salt.
Lay it out the cool, and then
that'll be the beginning
of the topping...
For our smoked slaw
and sausage pizza.
-Okay.
-Yep.
So the meat's had
24 hours to marinate.
Now we're just gonna
render some off.
Got to go in small batches.
You want this to clump
up a little bit,
render some of the fat
so it doesn't stick.
So you brown that off.
-Brown this up.
-Great.
And now we're ready
to start making the pizza?
That's it.
Stretch it out to order.
So, we'll take that.
The dough goes in the oven
for about 3 minutes.
Pull this skin out.
Nice rise.
[ Whistles ]
Red onion marmalade,
give it a thin coat.
Get that meat on there.
So I got some sausage here.
That's ready to go back
in the oven. A couple minutes.
-Okay.
-Pizza's about ready.
Nice crust.
Boom.
Let's just drape it
with some of our slaw.
Look at that!
Cut it here.
Nice, crisp crust.
No cheese and no sauce.
♪♪
Dude, smoking the slaw --
genius.
Really, really good.
On the tomato front,
looking for the acid,
you're getting the acid
from the onion.
Mmm.
But the kicker, the slaw,
because of the mayo,
because of that fat,
is reminiscent of the fat
that you'd need from the cheese.
I don't know that if you
blindfolded somebody...
Mmm.
...the average person
would really be able to say
there's absolutely no cheese
and there's absolutely no sauce.
I'm not gonna be able
to stop eatin' that.
Here's your sausage
and slaw pizza.
It's just amazing.
It's so fresh.
FIERI: I got to talk about
that pizzetta, man.
Give the booze away and just
charge $9,000 for the pizzetta.
I think what really
ties it together
is actually just
the slaw and the onion.
Duck confit,
ready to go.
I can't reiterate the care that
goes into the fresh ingredients
and to the cooking.
Mozzarella and gazpacho,
ready to go!
It's like something that
you just grew in your garden.
This is the BLT pizza.
Look at the tomatoes.
They're heirlooms.
-Crazy.
-Favorite thing on the menu?
-A couple tacos for you.
-The tacos.
Favorite thing
on the menu?
Bánh mí.
Same thing.
Eat it every day.
FIERI: Billy's version of
the Vietnamese classic.
-Order up!
-It's delicious.
So what do you got?
Start with the pork loin
for the bánh mí,
lightly trim it up,
cut it into thirds.
Okay.
We brine it overnight,
put in some extra flavor.
Pull it out
and marinate it.
Hoisin, sriracha,
fresh-ground black pepper.
How long does it need
to marinate?
An hour.
All right.
So what are we making now?
Our jalapeño aioli.
Got it.
We got to extract some of the
liquid out of this jalapeño.
-Just the liquid itself?
-Just the liquid.
Rough chop 'em.
Crack open the cells.
Yes. Push it through a chinois.
This is a fine strainer.
Pure jalapeño juice.
Look at that, man.
Now we're ready for our aioli.
Start with our egg yolks,
fresh-squeezed lime juice,
macerated garlic.
Breaks down real easy.
Give it a little whisk.
-Where's your oil?
-You can do that for me.
Now, any reason we're not
using the food processor?
I like forearm workouts.
Now we add our jalapeño liquid.
So we season with
a little bit of salt.
Ready to go.
Taste this.
Oh-oh.
With that fresh lime juice.
Oh, yeah. Now we're going
to sear our pork.
First some oil.
Okay.
Take our loin and don't
overcrowd our pan.
You crowd the pan,
they sit there and steam,
they don't really build a crust
to the outside of them.
So, you'll mark these off and
then finish them in the oven?
Yeah.
About 25 minutes or so.
Cooled down.
Time to go.
Yep.
We'll get a nice,
thin slice.
Okay. Looking great.
Our little roll here.
We'll give it a little slice.
Some of the killer
jalapeño aioli.
Lay our pork on there.
Ah!
Some cucumbers,
blanched long beans,
pickled carrots, basil,
a bunch of cilantro.
Out of control.
Now, I've had bánh mí sandwiches
all over the country.
This is pushing the limits.
Mmm! Mmm-mmm-mmm.
-Are we in Flavortown?
-Your GPS is workin'.
The crunch, fresh veggies,
nice acid, the blanched beans.
Mmm. Fantastic.
The pork is right on point.
Pretty rock star.
Nice job, Billy.
Thank you.
Really nice job.
-And here's your bánh mí.
-It has a whole bunch
of different flavors in it.
-The pork is very flavorful.
Bánh mí, juicy Lucy!
I mean, this is the kind of
place we all want to own,
the kind of place
we all want to hang out.
Congratulations.
FIERI: Up next, I'm sticking
to Sactown...
-[ Whistles ]
-All right!
FIERI: ...'cause there's a
funky little French place...
And voilà.
...with an out-of-control
chef you just got to meet.
This is really how he is.
This is not a show.
You got to come watch this.
[ Singing indistinctly ]
So here's one for you.
Did you know that I was
an exchange student in France
when I was in high school? Huh?
Well, anyhow, I don't know
that everybody
really gets
the French food experience
like I did when I lived there.
So, I'm here in East Sacramento
at a place called Cafe Rolle
to get my French-food fix.
Et voilà, monsieur.
Quiche lorraine.
The food is fantastic.
Every time I come in here,
I try something new.
Mousse au chocolat.
This is like a Paris bistro.
-Bon appétit.
-All the herbs, the flavors.
Voilà.
Reminds me
of being in France.
-Bonjour, monsieur.
-And it ought to...
Chicken pâté appetizer.
...'cause William Rolle
grew up there.
He's from France originally.
FIERI: In Lyon,
where his parents ran
what's called a traiteur.
That's the French
version of a deli.
And I arrived here
10 years ago.
And opened up a place
just like Mom and Dad's.
We do the same recipes
from scratch at a decent price.
Et voilà, monsieur!
Fast food the French way.
Et voilà.
That means topping
salad with quiche.
Bon appétit.
A grilled ham
and cheese looks like this.
WOMAN: Warmed, French ham
with melted Brie cheese.
-The croque-monsieur.
-That's correct.
-And pâté...
-Allez pâté sandwich.
FIERI: ...is always on the menu.
People always ask me,
"What is pâté?"
I'm like, "French meatloaf."
French meatloaf.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
Chicken pâté.
Chicken pâté
with goat cheese.
Okay. Okay, the bowl.
Special bread
we put into skin.
Now we're going to
soak it in low-fat...
Low-fat?
...half-and-half cream.
Okay, chicken.
-How did the chicken get cooked?
With Provençal, salt,
and oil for 20 minutes.
So, chicken, slice it.
Da-na! Tack, tack.
Then, un...
Deux, trois.
All right, let's go
see the big boy.
This guy's nuts.
Now that's a serious grinder.
Okay, showtime.
[ Vocalizing ]
All right, parsley, and then
goat cheese, and then...
-Okay.
-We mix it.
With?
With...
-Your foot?
-I'll be back.
-[ Whistles ]
-All right!
Then mix it.
Goes in the oven
45 minutes.
350?
As soon as the top
is brown, it's done.
You guys should put it on a
stick and sell it at the fair.
-[ Laughs ] Hey, not a bad idea.
-Yeah.
So, we're done,
we're cooled.
We cut it, take it out.
Ha-ha!
Little baguette,
little mustard, and voilà.
Mmm. That is really good.
Great flavor,
real nice and moist.
The combination between
the Herbs de Provence,
the goat cheese
and the chicken,
a little bit of the parsley,
excellent.
This is the only place
that you can get it.
The quality of the food
for the price.
I'm pleasantly surprised.
FIERI: No wonder the office
lunch crowd is packing in.
She came back to work
and was just raving
about the restaurant.
Et voilà, Madame.
They love it.
Getting me into French food
which I never have had before.
Tastes, you know,
like it does over there.
When I lived in France,
the way I would eat
was a lot like this.
-Yes.
-It's a lot of salads,
a lot of cold sandwiches
and small dishes.
I think when most people
think French restaurant,
they think escargot, they think
everything is big and rich.
Yeah, this is more
country-style, casual-style.
FIERI: The way William learned
from his folks back in Lyon.
Okay, is it ready to go?
Oh, yeah.
Like smoking salmon
from his dad's own recipe.
My dad teach me.
And you're making salmon
all the time?
All the time.
That's my speciality.
60 pounds a week, smoked over
hickory and sliced by hand.
What do we got here,
a little dill, uh...?
Little dill, créme fraîche.
That's all you need.
Good, huh?
With the dill, delicious.
-Oh, yeah.
-I'm telling you,
it's wonderful.
-It's delicious.
-It's really fresh.
You know, that's what
you get in France.
Just simple, fresh food.
FIERI: Like this classic lentil
vinaigrette salad from Lyon...
Very familiar.
...that William's topping
with roasted prawns.
We're gonna make marinated
prawn on the lontil.
Lentil.
Lentil salad.
First, we get the lentil.
Just regular lentils?
Regular lentil.
They don't even
have to be French.
Then chicken stock.
Yes.
Then wine.
Don't put too much wine.
1 cup.
That's a lot more
than 1 cup.
There we go.
A French cup.
Then a little of
the Provence, and voilà.
We put it on the stove
for 20 minutes.
Hup!
Now?
We need the prawn,
some Provençal.
Lavender, thyme, basil.
Directly from France.
It's the good stuff.
It smells fantastic.
Then...
Some shallots.
Okay.
-Some garlic, some parsley.
That's interesting. You're using
curly parsley versus flat-leaf.
Yes. In France, that's what
we use and I'm used to it.
Okay. And then oil.
And this is gonna be
the marinade for the shrimp.
We're gonna put it in
the oven 300 Fahrenheit.
How long?
13 minutes.
Not 12, not 14. 13.
Our lentils
have cooked down.
Now what do we do?
French vinaigrette.
This is Dijon mustard,
soybean oil,
and a little bit
of red wine vinegar.
Then some Provençal,
salt, then stir.
Then we're gonna
put the shrimp
on top of the cold
lentil salad.
Et voilà.
♪♪
Mmm. Perfect on the shrimp.
You're right.
[ French accent ]
Not 12 minutes or 14.
13.                 13.
[ Normal voice ] Mmm. The Dijon
vinaigrette coats it nicely.
Blended together, it's segmented
flavors and textures.
The Herbs de Provence
take a very floral note.
Back that tape
up a second.
...floral note.
Yep. I said floral note.
It has a lot of flavor.
Salted shrimp, cooked perfectly.
The food is wonderful.
You come in here,
they speak French.
-Bon appétit.
-Fun atmosphere with great food.
I bring somebody
new here every week.
Really?
I do.
♪ Bum-bum-bum
bum-bum-buh ♪
American people love
the food.
They can't wait to come back.
He's got so much personality.
It brings us coming
back every time.
This is really how he is.
This is not a show.
You got to come watch this.
[ Singing indistinctly ]
FIERI: Comin' up,
a San Francisco spot
serving up Southern classics.
Everything going on
in this is outstanding.
Then a small-town joint
with big-time pizza...
Should've made one
for yourself.
...thanks to a monster oven.
Got to dig this, man.
♪♪
You have got to dig
San Francisco.
I mean, all the cool
little areas,
the neighborhoods,
the districts.
Well, here I am in the southeast
side of the Mission District
to check out a joint
that started in the '30s
as an Italian restaurant
in a garage.
Well, fast forward to 2006,
and now it's a funky
little joint
that's serving up some killer
Southern comfort food.
Oh, that's right.
You got to come kick it
at the Front Porch.
♪♪
Table 7, Frito pie.
Bucket of chicken.
This is my favorite restaurant.
Crawfish étoufée fries.
I know the food in my city.
And you say
that that is it.
This is the only game
in town.
FIERI: For honest to goodness
Southern food,
thanks to friends
and business partners
Josey White and Kevin Cline.
We were always
talking about,
"This neighborhood needs
one more funky little joint."
This place became available,
and she gave me a call.
And the two partners brought in
comfort-food-cooking chef
Matt Marcus...
Mac and cheese, table 7.
FIERI: ...to introduce
down-home favorites
to the city by the bay,
like this Southern staple.
Shrimp and grits in the window!
My favorite thing on the menu.
Okay, what are we
gonna make first?
First,
we're gonna make grits
for our shrimp and grits.
We're gonna start
with whole milk,
water,
and unsalted butter.
And we're gonna just
let this come to a boil.
And then we're gonna add
our stone-ground grits,
fresh-ground black pepper,
and plenty of kosher salt.
Grits need a lot of salt.
-I agree with you.
So we'll let
these cook down.
Yep.
For 45 minutes.
The last thing we want to add
is sharp cheddar cheese.
[ Whistles ]
Next up, we're making?
Creole seasoning.
Start with kosher salt,
black pepper,
white pepper,
cayenne pepper...
[ Whistles ]
...paprika,
dark chili powder.
I like
where this is going.
We have coriander, cumin,
and last
is ground mustard.
And we just whisk this
all together.
And that's it.
Red-eye gravy.
Okay, so let's get into it.
We're gonna start
with some canola oil,
rough-chopped shallots.
-A lot of them.
Garlic...
and andouille sausage...
a generous portion of our
creole spice that we just made,
and we're just gonna cook
this down a little bit.
We want those spices
to kind of toast.
So, from there, we're gonna add
Worcestershire sauce...
Tabasco.
A lot of it.
Well, it's called
"spicy shrimp and grits."
Hence.
We do
chicory coffee here...
and chicken stock.
That you make yourself,
of course.
Absolutely. We're gonna bring it
to a boil,
let it simmer
for about 45 minutes.
So, now we're on to start
our shrimp and grits.
A generous ladle of the red-eye
gravy that we just made.
As if it's not
spicy enough,
we're gonna add a little bit
of our creole spice
and a little bit of butter.
And we're gonna add
our wild gulf shrimp.
Soak up
all that great flavor.
I am dying to taste
that sauce.
[ Imitates siren ]
Plate it up.
Flavor jets.
All right, so we have
our nice creamy, cheesy grits.
We'll do our shrimp
right on top.
And the reduced red-eye gravy
with all the sausage and...
Fixins.
...fixins.
[ Gruff voice ] Then I put
the fixins on there!
And last,
we have to add green onions.
And there you go.
[ Normal voice ] Let's just get
right into this right now.
This isn't exactly
how I know red-eye gravy
to be where I'm from,
but I will tell you
it is awesome.
Got a little coffee kick.
I mean, it's rich.
Grits are cheesy.
The andouille is spot-on.
Everything going on
in this is outstanding,
but really the crescendo
is those fresh shrimp.
I mean, succulent.
Have I ever used that word
on "Triple D"?
Oh, my gosh.
Killer dish.
Cool.
Glad you like it.
WOMAN:
The shrimp and grits.
The spicy shrimp
and grits were amazing.
The grits themselves
are great.
You can eat them with a fork,
which, to me, is the true test.
It's got that spicy sausage,
which I just wolfed down.
The Front Porch
makes you feel at home.
WOMAN #2:
I love the rocking chairs.
They remind you
of your childhood,
and you know if
there's a rocking chair,
you're gonna have
a rocking time.
FIERI:
Small, little kitchen,
and a chef with a lot
of personality.
It's awesome.
Cool. Thank you very much.
Enjoyed it.
♪♪
FIERI: Now I'm headed
out of the city
to a small spot
just over an hour north.
About 35 miles
west of Sacramento
is a little town
called Winters.
Now, they're known
for great agriculture,
especially their walnuts.
Now, there's only a handful
of restaurants in town,
and one of the favorites --
it's actually
the second restaurant
that was opened here --
is knockin' 'em out
with wood-fired pizzas
and a made-from-scratch menu.
This is Putah Creek Café.
MAN: We got a Mediterranean.
The best pizza you have ever
had in your life.
-Fresh artichoke hearts.
-Home-grown food.
WOMAN: Shrimp and heirloom
tomato salad.
Fred in the kitchen,
such a great job.
FIERI: That'd be
Chef Fred Reyes...
Western burger coming up.
...who's got 35 years
in the biz...
Smoked salmon appetizer.
...from white-tablecloth
joints...
Three chicken salads.
...to mom and pops.
Burger coming up.
And now he's making
his mark on Putah Creek.
First thing I thought about,
doing everything from scratch,
as much as possible.
Fresh berries and waffles up.
The breakfast,
my favorite, probably.
Biscuits and gravy.
The homemade sausage
is delectable.
They make it fresh every day.
It's amazing.
Okay, brother,
let's do sausage.
We're gonna start off
with a boneless pork butt.
Cut it in really thin pieces.
Holy "Pirates of the Caribbean"
sword.
You like that samurai?
Okay, so you're gonna
make that just so you
can just drop it
right into the feeder.
Exactly.
And that's
all she wrote.
So now we're gonna
chill this...
Yes.
...grind the spices.
Right.
Kosher salt, freshly-ground
pepper, dried sage.
Loves pork.
Granulated garlic.
-Yep.
-Dried thyme.
-T-T-Thyme. Onion?
-A little bit of onion powder,
rosemary, brown sugar,
a little bit of nutmeg,
cayenne pepper.
Some nice, dried chilies.
That's a great mix
you got, man.
Put a little plastic on it.
If I don't,
then it all goes up here
and then I got to
scrape it all out.
It's not his first rodeo.
We start on low speed
and work our way up.
That is awesome. He's pulverized
this into a dust.
You're just gonna blend
all throughout that pork.
This is like pro
pork sausage making.
Good fat to meat ratio.
That's just primetime.
Now a cup of ice water.
Adding moisture.
If not, you'll cook
all your fat out
and you'll be a little
bit on the drier side.
-About a 3-ounce patty.
-Good looking patty, man.
Now we'll go
cook 'em up?
A little olive oil
in the pan,
and let those cook
for a few minutes.
Flip 'em over.
Looks money.
Got some homemade biscuits
and homemade country
white gravy, homemade sausage.
Look at that. Mmm.
Delicious, man.
The sausage is super moist,
not overly seasoned.
Killer gravy.
Nice and silky.
That is great.
-Biscuits and gravy.
A great country gravy.
-The sausage is amazing.
-Burger with fries.
WOMAN:
Great people and great food,
it just brings
the community together.
FIERI: Exactly what owners
John Pickerel...
Have you had this one
before?
...and his wife,
Melanie Bajakian...
How are you today?
...were going for.
A place where people
could come to meet
and come
on a frequent basis.
And the folks are comin' for all
the pizza they're firing up,
with a custom-made
oven for pies,
like prosciutto and basil...
Very good. I definitely
recommend it.
-...classic pepperoni...
-Pepperoni and cheese!
FIERI: ...and even
herb-seasoned,
fresh-roasted chicken
for this fan favorite.
-Chicken pizza coming out.
-The chicken's moist and tender.
Chicken pizza.
The crust is thin
and crispy and perfect.
FIERI: And made totally
from scratch.
Okay. Pizza dough.
Give it to me.
Start off
with our cold water,
extra virgin olive oil,
kosher salt, dry yeast.
We use a really small
amount of yeast, too,
because it's gonna be
in there for two days.
With the cold water, the yeast
is now starting to grow.
Right. We're gonna add
our flour, and then local,
whole-wheat flour
from Woodland, California.
Let's turn this baby on.
It goes about 20 minutes.
It's pulled away
from the bowl.
Then we're gonna go right into
making our pizza dough balls,
portioning it out
to about 13 ounces,
set it in our pizza trays.
Lookin' good.
They're gonna go
into the walk-in.
Okay.
These guys have been in
the walk-in for two days.
A little moist to the touch.
they're ready to be rolled out.
Dust it.
And you're doing it
with a sheeter versus by hand?
We start if off this way, about
two or three times through it,
and then I'll stretch
it out a little bit,
put a little cornmeal
on my pie tin.
Now we're ready to top it.
Okay.
So put some mozzarella,
whole-milk,
oven-roasted chicken.
Not too much.
No sauce on this?
No sauce.
Some spinach that
we roasted in the oven.
Garlic cloves poached in
a little bit of olive oil,
the provolone will be
the last topping.
Should've made one
for yourself.
Ready to go.
Set it up.
I've seen some big ovens.
I've never seen one on a trailer
that you tow behind a truck.
FIERI: This thing is
smokin' hot -- 650 on the deck.
Should come up
in about 3 minutes.
-Ready to bring it out.
-Look at this thing.
Really good looking pie.
Get a little bit of garlic oil
around the edges,
sprinkle some fresh herbs,
some freshly-grated cheese.
Okay.
Good looking crust.
Mmm. I like the spinach.
Can't beat the roasted chicken.
Great crust,
dynamite pizza oven.
Package deal, man.
It's across the board.
Congrats, brother.
Brick chicken pizza.
The chicken is a little bit
salty, the cheese is fabulous.
-Perfectly crisp.
-Biscuits and sausage.
It's just a real
hometown feel.
Pinot up!
The quality's there,
the flavor's there,
and you're just gonna
enjoy your meal.
-Oven-roasted chicken up!
-You know how to cook, man.
You got your finger on the pulse
on how to do it right.
I'm impressed.
Really impressed.
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
We just had some cannelloni
that would what?
Ooh! Knock your mama
out the rockin' chair.
Knock your mama
out the ro--
We don't typically
use that line
on "Triple D."
[ Laughter ]