You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That place you went to
in that one town
that served that one dish,
how are they doing
after 'Triple D'?"
You know what? I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
[ Laughs ]
A firecracker in Portland
still dishing out
the classic comfort food,
but with a side of sass...
You're amazing. What do you do
in your spare time?
Fool around.
[ Laughs ]
...a pizza joint
in Jackson, Wyoming,
that's bringin' the funk...
That's my brother
from another mother.
...and I'm weighing in
on their newest creation
for "Triple-D Nation"...
You're gonna love this.
...and in Minneapolis...
"Sunday, Sunday, Sunday!"
...a lobster truck
who decided it was time
to go big or go home.
Just be ready.
Hey, and spoiler alert --
They didn't go home.
It's gonna be the stupidest
thing you've ever seen.
[ Tires squeal ]
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
I can't believe
it was just four years ago
that I was here
in Jackson, Wyoming...
Hot and ready.
Come and get it.
FIERI: ...to check out
this funky, little pizza join.
Are they doin' good?
You tell me.
Real nice.
To find a parking spot,
I had to come park in the alley.
This is the one
and only Pinky G's.
♪♪
What I like about Pinky G's
is you can get it by the slice,
calzones, killer wings.
Two slices!
Everybody comes here. All
my ski-bum friends come here.
All the locals come here.
Anybody who visits town,
everybody who has seen the show
will absolutely come here.
It's really low-key, it's quick,
so you can come
and grab a beer and a slice.
Spin it.
FIERI: I couldn't wait to see
how my favorite
chicken-dancing chef was doin'.
-How's life?
-Good, man.
-Good too see you.
-Been busy?
Uh, yeah.
Definitely.
When I first met Tom Fay,
he was a local kid
filling a void in his hometown.
No one was doing pizza
by the slice?
No. Just needed to be
up to par.
We needed some good pizza
in town.
Still, don't trust
a skinny cook.
Of course there was nerves
going on --
the fact that Guy was actually
gonna taste our pizza.
Funky Chicken.
Time to get down
with the Funky Chicken.
How'd you come up
with the name?
Uh, I just like to do
the bird dance.
Remember the Funky --
Can you do it?
[ Laughter ]
That's my brother
from another mother.
Just named it
the Funky Chicken
'cause the pizza had pesto
and roasted chicken on it.
Whatever. It's different.
Funky Chicken.
There's really no answer.
Roasting the chicken
with the garlic? Outrageous.
Making your own pesto?
Over the top.
There's one other person
that I know the Funky Chicken
is one of their favorite dances.
Let's get Aunt Polly
on the phone.
POLLY: Hey, honey.
Hi, Aunt Polly. How are you?
Can you give me
a little Funky Chicken?
-Sure.
-Okay, here we go.
How funky is your chicken?
How loose is your goose?
[ Laughing ]
All right! All right!
Thank you, Polly.
[ Laughter ]
So, do people come in
and ask for the dance?
Uh, they do.
Thanks a lot, buddy.
[ Laughter ]
I have regrets about that
every day.
And the fact your Aunt Polly
actually answered --
That is the worst part.
It's still --
Every time I see her,
she'll say something
to me about,
"Hey, how is
that Pinky G's doin'?" so...
It took about 2 1/2 weeks
before there was a line
out the door.
As it turns out,
being such a small community
with a lot of tourism,
it was all the people
visiting from out of town
that are fans of "Triple D."
You can always tell
when people are fans
if they order
the Funky Chicken.
Some ask me to dance,
which is not cool.
And the Abe Froman,
the sausage king of Chicago.
The Abe Froman,
I still love that.
All right.
Abe Froman comin' up.
FIERI: Abe Froman,
the sausage king of Chicago,
from "Ferris Bueller's
Day Off"?
Yes.
I'm impressed
with the throw, man,
especially with such
a low ceiling.
Let's add some sauce,
mozzarella cheese...
spicy Italian sausage...
buffalo mozz here.
Nice.
Little fresh basil on top.
Wow, that's hot.
Great. Why don't we go
to commercial for next week,
and we'll come back?
♪♪
It's too hold
to even hot --
-"It's too hold to even hot."
-Yeah, I got you.
Have you ever had it
when it's too hold to even hot?
I was nervous,
'cause I noticed
that I put a little
too much cheese on there.
It was starting to fall off.
♪♪
Sauce is tangy.
You are talkin' glutens.
You are talkin' chew.
You are talkin' texture.
You're talkin' money.
No wonder everybody
in town loves you.
It's off the hook, bro.
Great job.
Thanks, man.
Okay. So, what else is going on?
What else is happening?
We've been working on trying
to get a couple new pizzas
to throw on the menu.
We put a poll out
to the community to find out
what kind of pies they wanted.
And about 1,000 people voted,
and it turned out
it was just about dead even
all the way across the board,
so I suggested,
maybe we'll have Guy make
the executive decision.
Me can help us out
and put a new pizza on the menu.
What do you got?
We've got the meatball
Parm, baby.
FIERI: That starts with
their homemade meatballs.
Start off with equal parts
ground beef, ground pork,
grated Parm and Romano cheese,
pine nuts.
Mix it all up,
make some meatballs
little smaller
than tennis balls,
and 550 for about 25 minutes.
Let them cool down,
slice them up,
and top them on the pizza.
FIERI: He's also adding buffalo
mozzarella and more marinara
before throwing it in the oven.
So, what are you gonna
call this?
Fuggedaboudit.
And you haven't had this
on the menu before?
Nope.
♪♪
I'm surprised that's not
on the menu already.
Meatball pie comin' out.
I like this pizza, and I think
it's really worth
being on the menu.
It's got a good mix
of meat and cheese
with a little bit of greenery.
Hittin' all the buckets.
We didn't talk
about this one.
Yeah, I know.
Buffalo chicken --
See, if I think
it's gonna be buffalo,
I'm thinking it's really
got to be buffalo.
-Yeah.
-Why don't we make it?
-Want to make one?
-You got any wing sauce?
-Sure do.
-Let's make it.
All right.
FIERI: When we come back,
I'm putting on the apron...
-10 minutes.
-In we go.
...and we're getting down
with the buffalo chicken.
Bye-bye!
Thanks for calling Pinky G's.
This is Guy. Can I help you?
Four years ago, I went to pizza
joint in Jackson, Wyoming...
Abe Froman comin' up.
...where Tom Fay was slingin'
dough for his loyal customers
since he opened
the joint in 2011.
This is our friend
Timmy McClure,
and he's been coming
to Pinky G's
every day
since we've been open.
He has begged me
to come and meet you
-if you ever came back to town.
-Absolutely.
Every time I see that car
of yours,
I want to see if you had time
for, like, a photo with me.
-Absolutely.
-Dude, that would be awesome.
We're gonna
make it happen.
All right.
There we go.
Now, where's the chain?
Take your chain out.
You tell me this is not
the stunt double
for "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
FAY:
He and Guy hit it off right.
He's got the chain and
the swagger like Guy does, too.
FIERI:
Tom has his true fans,
so when it came time
to add to the menu,
he turned to them
for their input,
having them vote
on their favorite new pie.
Now, it's a dead heat
between the Fuggedaboudit
and the buffalo chicken,
so I'm jumping in
to help break the tie.
See, I'm thinking it's really
got to be buffalo.
-Yeah?
-Why don't we make it?
♪♪
To knock out
a buffalo chicken pizza...
-Yeah.
-...let's start off
with a couple of the basics.
Ricotta, just a touch,
and a little bit
of that blue cheese.
Grab some mozz.
-Mozza!
-Let's go mozz.
Now we've got chopped-up,
fried chicken tenders
on one side, like this.
We'll try chopped up...
And the roasted chicken
on the other?
...roasted chicken breast
on the other.
I think that, because
we're in a pizza joint,
you got to kiss it with a little
bit of shredded pepperoni.
And then, last but not least,
the wing sauce.
We're not gonna toss
all the chicken in it right now,
because it'll go ahead
and make the chicken too soggy.
Little kiss on the crust.
What do you think?
-Let's see what we got.
-Give it a shot?
Yeah.
Okay.
Half and half.
Make anything taste good
with that dough.
Now I thought we would drizzle
a little bit
of the cold blue cheese
right on top.
Ooh, nice.
And then do a little bit
of the wing sauce
that didn't get
cooked in yet.
♪♪
Oh.
[ Laughs ]
Uh-huh.
-Uh-huh.
-Bye-bye.
That is good.
I like it with
the roasted chicken.
I think you might get a little
bit better chicken flavor.
-What do you think?
-Sold.
I don't think there's
a buffalo chicken dance.
There's not
Thank God.
I'm gonna leave you up
to make it.
WOMAN: So, this is
my buffalo chicken pizza,
and it's absolutely delicious.
Buffalo chicken comin' out.
WOMAN: It's a little spicy, but,
you know, it makes you feel
like you're living
on the edge a bit.
I think we pulled the trigger
on the buffalo chicken.
Comin' out.
Well, it takes a couple things
that I love,
chicken wings and pizza,
and marries them.
This is a pizza that I would
order time and time again.
We're still up for discussion
on the name,
but we got a couple good ones.
"Triple D Nation" Pizza.
Guy's Pie. The Funky Fieri.
Roll with it.
What else?
Anything else new?
-Married, wife, kids.
-What?
Just had twins
eight weeks ago.
-Whoa.
-Yeah.
Still here workin' all the time,
even though you're a dad now.
I'll tell you, the reason
you have such great success
is because you're real,
and you're involved,
and you're taking
care of business,
-and you didn't wander away.
-Never in a million years
would I think
that you'd come back, so...
Oh, I told you I was
coming back, dude.
After Aunt Polly says
the Funky Chicken, I got to --
And I didn't know you could
come down one time a year,
and you come down and actually
see the Funky Chicken happen.
♪♪
So, my guess is, Tom's gonna
have a line out the door
just waiting to see that dance.
Now, Tom, make sure you send
a little video my way.
And next up, we're checking in
on this ball of fire.
Hey, diner guy! You want to race
for some pink slips?
She's been keeping a map
of the "Triple D Nation"...
It's unbelievable
when every continent
in the world's visited you.
FIERI:
...and feeding them, too.
Oh, yeah.
FIERI: Five years ago
in Troutdale, Oregon,
about 18 miles
outside of Portland,
I met this little firecracker
named Shirley.
And I got to tell you,
she hasn't changed one bit.
This is Shirley's Tippy Canoe.
♪♪
Here you go.
Ooh, that looks tasty.
By golly, it will be.
Shirley's Tippy Canoe is
full of life, just like Shirley.
-You've got it down.
-I'm practicing.
Everything Shirley does
is homemade and fresh.
Okay girls,
here's your veggie burgers.
-Thank you.
-Just great food,
a great restaurant,
and a fantastic host.
FIERI: And she certainly didn't
tone it down for the camera.
You're amazing. What do you
do in your spare time?
Fool around.
[ Laughs ]
And I do get married
a lot.
-I'll be over here.
-[ Laughs ]
Well, what's a woman
supposed to do?
This is starting to get
a little surreal.
What are we gonna make?
We got a cornucopia of spices.
We're making gunpowder.
That's our spice.
All of this
goes to gunpowder?
And there's nothing that we make
that we don't use it in.
-Really?
-Uh-huh.
-So the French toast?
-No, not the French toast.
Okay. That's one.
Salt. Paprika.
Then we're gonna go ahead
and put some celery salt in it.
SHIRLEY:
So, we were making seasonings,
and that has 19
ingredients in it.
I've never had more fun
mixing spices.
We had a good time.
Snap it down. Okay.
Yeah. All right.
-Gunpowder.
-Gunpowder!
I feel I'm in the Wild West.
Whoo!
-You are.
-I am?
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
She's not wrong. This joint's
kind of got a shady past.
SHIRLEY: This restaurant had
been a roadhouse, built in 1932.
I had my first cocktail
in this bar.
But every owner
was their own best customer.
It was pretty rough.
So I went ahead and bought it,
knowing what I was getting into.
FIERI: That was in 2007,
and the neighbors
were more than a bit skeptical.
When we opened it, they were
a little bit apprehensive,
but I'll tell you
what really made the difference.
"Triple D" came,
and that made
this restaurant respectable.
-Pork butt to make the --
-The sausage.
-The Polish sausage?
-Mm-hmm.
-This a big seller?
-Oh, yes.
-Get it goin'.
-All right. Here we go.
'Cause we don't
have all day.
[ Shakily ] I don't know.
I can't hold onto it any longer.
Well, let's just stop it.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
We're gonna
make the patty.
About 7 ounces.
The au jus is ready.
Nice little toast
on that.
Here we are.
[ Whistles ]
Paul Bunyan, or what?
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
-That's crazy.
-It's good, isn't it?
SHIRLEY: The menu hasn't
changed particularly.
It's still all cooked
from scratch.
FIERI: And one that's top
of the charts these days
is Shirley's deconstructed
Shrimp Meltdown.
One of the most popular items
that we have
is called the Shrimp Meltdown,
and that's layers of sourdough
bread, fresh mushrooms,
top it with
our homemade chowder.
FIERI: And the chowder's got
just what you'd expect --
tons of clams, clam juice,
bacon, and onions.
It doesn't get any better.
Then bay shrimp and cheese
to top it off
before hitting the oven.
Decadent, to me.
[ Laughs ]
It's decadent.
I love her clam chowder,
so I figured
this was going to be something
I was gonna love.
FIERI: Now, I originally
stopped by for dinner,
but what I didn't know is that
Shirley is doing
a bangin' breakfast, too.
♪♪
The breakfast menu
is very popular,
especially on the weekends.
Guy did miss out.
FIERI:
And the one dish this hometown
crowd can't get enough of
is their seafood-stuffed
Newburg omelet.
SHIRLEY: We make our omelet
with seven eggs.
Once it's cooked and was
flipped over twice, we stuff it
with Swiss cheese,
the Newburg sauce --
halibut, salmon, tuna,
and scallops
inside the Newburg sauce.
Here's your
Newburg omelet.
-Enjoy.
-Thank you.
MAN:
It's creamy. It blends well.
It's just enjoyable.
♪♪
More blooper, baby.
[ Laughs ]
[ Both laugh ]
She's the real seller --
her food,
and she personally
really sells this place.
This map is from
the United States.
Everybody from every state
has been here.
I had no idea how strong
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives" was.
It gives your exposure
all over the world, literally.
-Want to see where we're at?
-Yeah.
It's unbelievable
when every continent
in the world's visited you,
and that was something that was
pretty overwhelming to me
when this all began.
But it gives you a feeling of
you're doing something correct,
and making people happy
is the biggest achievement
you can have.
Very nice job.
It is [Whistles]
-Thanks.
-That means "darn good."
[ Laughs ]
Yeah. In the whistle vocabulary,
[Whistles]
means "darn good."
-Okay. Well, we're whistlin'.
-You just remember that.
Yes, we are whistlin'.
Man, I am glad that that place
hasn't changed one bit.
And, Shirley, you stay
the same as always,
except no more racing
for pink slips.
And coming up, a place
that's done a complete 180,
when a lobster-loving chef
turned his little truck...
Round and round!
...into a crustacean sensation.
Lobster versus lobster,
only seen on "Triple D."
No more bets.
When "Triple D" came to
Minneapolis seven years ago,
I met Josh...
"Sunday, Sunday, Sunday!"
...a lobster-loving chef
cookin' up some righteous meals
out of the back of a bar.
-Look at that.
-Dunkify.
His lamb sandwich
and lobster mac
were the definition
of outrageous, stupid delicious.
Stupid!
Now he's traded in his truck
for an 8,000-square-foot
flagship restaurant,
complete with custom
lobster tanks.
This is Smack Shack.
All right.
Let's roll, guys.
Great seafood, lobster rolls,
the shrimp.
I mean, just fantastic.
Lucy up. Zack up.
Lobster roll.
If "Triple D" thinks that
it's good enough to feature,
then it's good enough
to put in my mouth.
FIERI: Now, when I first
rolled up to Smack Shack...
Shrimp po' boys up.
...Chef Josh Thoma
was the main man
for lobster in Minneapolis.
But you know I got
to keep him guessing,
so I started with something
completely off-script.
SERVER:
Roasted lamb sandwich.
-We're making lamb.
-Making lamb.
We got our bone-in
leg of lamb.
JOSH: Out of all the things
Guy picked,
when he picked
that lamb sandwich,
I was like...
because it's just
a lot of moving parts.
You know they'll
come in boned out?
Yeah, but then I don't
get the bones.
The bones are the key
to the juice.
We're gonna tie
a little surgeon's knot here.
And it takes a lot
of work to do.
Sponge, please.
[ Laughs ]
Boned, rolled, and tied.
But the reason it's on the menu
is 'cause it's something
that I love to eat.
Here we go.
Fire.
♪♪
It's outrageous.
This has got to be
in the top greatest
lamb sandwiches I've had.
I mean, it was crazy.
I had a guy
come in the next day,
flew up from Dallas,
just to have the lamb sandwich,
said, "I had some miles.
I had to have it."
You touch that sandwich,
I'll kill you.
I'm not touching
anything.
Oh, cameras are on?
I'm sorry.
Maybe you'd like a bite.
No, you're not hungry?
Fine.
I was really happy
that he chose that,
because it's really something
very much different
from the rest
of the stuff we do.
FIERI: That's because the rest
of Smack Shack's menu
is built around lobster.
All right. Next up, we're gonna
do our lobster mac and cheese
with Taleggio cheese
and sweet corn.
Dude, that's fondue.
That's fonduta.
And our lobster
goes right in,
get the toss, toss, toss.
-I'm with you.
-You got it?
I'm not goin' anywhere.
-Tiny portion?
-Nappy-time portion.
I'm gonna put that
in the Flavortown dictionary.
Ridiculous.
JOSH:
So, the lobster mac and cheese
and the lamb sandwich
are still on the menu.
People constantly come in
and ask for them.
They're gonna be there
forever and ever.
-Hi, everybody.
-Hi!
FIERI: But there's also
some new heavy hitters on there.
This is our original menu.
This is where we're at now,
with all of our various brunch,
dinner, lunch menus.
♪♪
FIERI:
Almost everything has Josh's
signature seafood stamp on it,
like this twist on
the classic Minnesota staple,
Fontina and Taleggio cheese
stuffed Juicy Lucy --
And you got to see it
to believe it.
You got to be really gentle
with these guys,
'cause otherwise, you can
push out the cheese.
We're gonna put it on a griddled
bun, add caramelized onions.
It's a lobster Lucy,
so, obviously, we put
a butter-poached
lobster claw right on top.
It's cheese, meat, and lobster.
It's a taste sensation
like no other.
I think any time you add
lobster, it's always good.
FIERI: And if you think
their menu's expanded,
wait till you see
the new restaurant.
1029 was about
1,500 square feet.
We're around
8,500 square feet here.
We had around five employees.
Now we have 130.
I've never come here when
it's empty. It's always packed.
FIERI: And when the Triple D
Nation came callin',
he gave them
just what they asked for --
more lobster.
Live Maine lobster
in Minneapolis.
Couldn't you just get
some processed lobster meat?
Could.
I like doing it myself.
So, he's got this incredible,
super-sized,
two-level lobster tank
that can hold
up to 400 live lobsters,
and it sits right next
to a 100-gallon lobster boil.
Doesn't get anything
better than that.
Round and round!
The lobster boil is kind of
almost like an altar.
I kind of wanted it
to be the centerpiece
where everyone could stand
around, talk to the chef...
No more bets.
...and sit and watch
these guys make lobster.
-Winner!
-Whoo!
FIERI: And when you're ordering
a lobster boil,
you're ordering by the pound.
JOSH: You can go anywhere
from a pound and 1/2
up to 6-pound lobster.
What you do is, it comes with
all-you-can-eat sausage, corn,
and potatoes, but 50 pounds
of onions goes into it.
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
It comes out,
gets butchered on the table,
cracked open,
and then put into a bowl.
♪♪
-Lobster boil?
-Yeah!
FIERI: You add a little
seafood seasoning and butter,
and the whole shebang gets
dumped right on the table.
Whoo!
Nice, spicy lobster and shrimp.
It's a taste sensation
like no other.
It's a Minnesota icicle
right here.
You know the whole
farm-to-table thing?
This is almost like
tank-to-table.
We go through more lobster
than everywhere else
in the state
of Minnesota combined.
Smack Shack attack.
You put the "K" in "class,"
my friend.
You got it.
So, let me ask you this -- What
does a pizza joint in Jackson,
a roadhouse dive in Portland,
and a lobster-obsessed shack
in Minneapolis
all have in common? Wait for it.
Exactly! You --
the Triple D Nation.
Hi, diner guy!
You lost fair and square.
Where's the pink slip?
Got it right here.
Thank you very much.
[ Laughter ]