You know, folks ask me
all the time --
"Hey, Guy, that place
you went to in that one town
that served that one dish,
how are they doing after
"Triple D"?"
You know what, I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation".
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all...
This is ridiculous, dude.
...but it turns out,
it was only the beginning,
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
a Flavortown trifecta booming
with biscuits in Denver,
a crazy Chicago
twosome who hit big
with their little location...
I mean, this is awesome.
...an Illinois spot
with a love connection,
and a taste of Trinidad we just
got to get back to in Seattle.
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors --
that's all right here,
right now
on "Triple D Nation".
♪♪
So, here's the story.
In Chicago, 2011 --
I think it was March --
I went to check out
a funky little place
where two buddies were
serving up fish & chips --
I called it The Whale.
They also did some
foie gras fries
and a pork belly po'boy
that would blow your mind.
What takes place?
Well, about a week
before the show airs,
they changed
to a larger location
because they knew that the
"Triple D Nation" was coming.
This is BIG & little's.
I got a fish & chip.
One spicy beef short rib taco,
a fish & chip,
and a Zeus burger.
We first heard about
BIG & little's while watching
"Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives".
Check it.
Chickity-check, Mike.
[ Laughs ]
We were just amazed
by the menu that they had.
-It's got a great atmosphere...
-I got it right here.
...Gary and Tony are just
really great guys,
and you can't go wrong
with the food.
What can I get for you?
FIERI: When I first met
Gary, or "BIG",
and Tony --
well, he's the "little" --
they were just
a couple of buddies
with a passion for food --
not exactly the most refined
chefs I've ever met.
-Ohhh!
-He got him again!
-No!
-Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
So, we'll let
this set out f--
You know, I just --
Being with Guy was great
because his energy level
is just like
a big fireball.
You could tell he just loves
to be around food.
What are we up to, boss?
Alright, we're gonna do
foie gras and fries.
So, what I'm gonna do
is I do fresh-cut fries,
take the foie gras --
nothing in the pan.
Ready to rock?
I'm ready to rock, man.
♪♪
What you have here is perfectly
cooked, medium rare,
nice, juicy ladling
of the duck fat
onto the super-crispy
shoestring fries.
STRAUSS:
I mean, we still have people
that just got off the plane,
they saw us on the show
a few years ago,
and they literally came here
in a taxi
with their luggage and rolled in
to get foie gras and fries.
Thanks, guys.
FIERI:
And you can't forget about
the monster fish & chips.
This is le cod.
My customers call it
"The Whale".
Dredge it with some flour,
put it in the fryer --
you got to stand back.
Evidently.
And it floats!
Here we go.
Whoa.
It's a beauty, isn't it?
Look at that.
Wow.
You can hear the sound effects,
the crackle.
Just listen to this.
It's tender,
not dried out,
and the crunch
on the outside of that --
you can't beat that
with a stick.
2011, we shoot "Triple D".
The place we shot was this tiny,
little, narrow spot --
I remember it.
-It was like 600 square feet.
Six stools.
I told you,
"You better be ready.
'Triple D's' coming."
What did you guys do?
We got ready.
So, we moved down the block.
So, you left
your location.
STRAUSS:
We left the location,
we opened up here
about a week
before the show aired.
We even took out the bar
that we had,
and we put it over here
to replicate the same bar,
so our regular customers
that come back get to sit there
and talk to us.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
Those are the original
six stools.
It looks like you haven't done
a thing to them.
Is that the actual one --
That's the sheet rock
out of the wall?
Yeah, we cut the drywall
out and took it with us.
Holy -- man,
that was a long time ago.
I don't think we got
our security deposit
back, by the way.
It was definitely
worth the move.
We have a lot more space,
we have a lot more seating,
we have a much
larger kitchen,
which allows us to make
a larger menu.
Look at this.
One of our best sellers
is the ahi poke crunch wrap.
You know, raw tuna --
It's like a good piece
is like butter.
A little bit of chili paste
and a little bit of sesame oil,
and it's a real
simple marinade.
Put rice in there, mixed greens
with a tostada, wasabi mayo.
And I'm gonna fold.
We're gonna put it
on the griddle.
This is your ahi
poke crunch wrap.
♪♪
This is everything you love
about a poke bowl,
but easy to eat
in a tortilla.
I mean, this is awesome.
The poke crunch wrap
is one of my favorites.
You have the sweet,
the spice, the crunch.
And it's just a taste
explosion in your mouth.
One shrimp and fry.
This is what I think tripped
people out when they saw
BIG & little's the first time
back in 2011 --
is they see two guys
that look like
they like chicken wings,
burgers, fries.
We do.
We do, but you take it
to the next level.
FIERI: Like with this bad boy --
the Zeus burger.
That's a fried egg, beef patty,
and gyro meat all piled
inside a hamburger bun.
And they're rocking a spicy
beef short rib taco.
D'ALESSANDRO: We shred it, and
then we sear it on the griddle
and serve it
with a sweet chili Thai sauce
and some onions
and cilantro.
So, coming from...
a guy that
eats a lot of tacos --
texture's great,
glad you didn't junk it up
with a bunch of stuff...
Right.
...a little onion,
a little cilantro,
good tang, can't beat it.
It's got a little
sweet side to it,
but it's also that
little spicy kick
that really brings
it all together.
MAN: Perfectly cooked meat,
and it's the same flavor
all the way through,
which I love about it.
It's the consistency.
FIERI: Now these guy's
got four locations.
This is taking the opportunity
and running with it.
Well, you're godfathers now.
You're made.
But if you're talking about
a culinary godmother...
That's killer.
...she's served me up
one of my favorite tastes
of Trinidad in Seattle,
of all places...
We're gonna make
some Paratha roti.
Write that down.
...and "Triple D Nation"
took notice.
We had a line that went
all the way around the block.
So, back in '09, I was in
Seattle's University District,
and I was going to
check out a joint
that was known for
this knockout Trinidad food.
Now, as soon as I tasted it,
I told Pam,
"Listen, you got to get ready
for a line out the door,"
and she did.
It's a new location,
but the food is still rocking.
This is Pam's Kitchen.
♪♪
Beef order.
Jerk chicken dinner.
Trinidad food is a combination
of creole and Indian.
Just very tasty.
It makes your mouth
just keep wanting to eat it.
Jerk chicken.
It's very quaint and has
a great atmosphere,
and it's absolutely delicious.
We watch the "Triple D"
all the time,
and we saw Pam's story,
and, you know,
Ms. Pam knows
what she's doing.
Okay, we have a goat head salad.
So, Pam Jacob -- I mean,
she started as a housekeeper
with 1,500 bucks
to open this location.
It's gonna be fine.
Don't you even worry
about this, Pam.
I mean, she puts her heart
into everything she makes.
So, we're making buttery,
flaky bread?
Yeah.
It's called...
parley the rotary?
Paratha --
Paratha roti.
We're gonna make
some Paratha roti.
Write that down.
In Trinidad, it's also
called the buss up shut.
Oh, gosh, don't start.
He threw in a little joke
in between.
Could be risky.
I love that guy.
We're gonna do
the Dahlpuri.
So, we start --
I use 7 cups of flour.
Uh, Pam,
that's not a cup.
Seven of this,
but it's 4 cups.
Yeah.
Her method's
a little unconventional,
a little strange to me.
I think he takes the food
really well.
He was rolling the roti,
and it was like perfect.
Oh, my goodness.
This is amazing.
Get that on tape.
We're gonna start beating
that roti.
JACOB: Guy never had
Trinidadian food before.
All for you at home.
I'm just suffering through
this right now.
Let me feel the pain.
That's killer.
I feel very happy
that he tasted mine first.
We're gonna make pelau.
Some salt...
Black pepper.
...a little habanero,
of course.
One of my customers would
describe my pelau as jambalaya,
but I've never had jambalaya,
so I used that on him.
In New Orleans, there's a mix up
with all the rices and all that.
Jambalaya.
Right.
This is similar to it but
with a whole lot more flavor.
I never had it.
Mmm. The rice
is nice and tender,
the chicken thigh is moist.
Mmm.
That was delicious.
Every thing I've had here
has been delicious.
Crazy, but delicious.
Crazy.
I like that one.
Before he leave, he give me
the biggest hug, and he said,
"Not tomorrow..."
[Voice breaking] He said,
"Not tomorrow -- today --
you should extend this place
because
you're gonna have a line."
And I did.
We had a line --
We had a line that went
all the way around the block.
FIERI: So, she picked up and
moved to a bigger place,
plus added a few new things
to her menu
like her Trinidadian take on
Jamaican jerk pork ribs.
So, we start with ketchup,
soy sauce, barbecue sauce
for the smokiness, sugar.
FIERI: But it's the habaneros
that she throws in
that really kicks up
the spice factor.
JACOB: So, I'm making sure
it's really well-coated
and gives it
that spicy goodness.
So, this is now ready
for temperature 145 for 1 hour.
The pork spare ribs.
It starts off with a nice,
sweet flavor,
and then the spice
comes in towards the end.
It's super flavorful
and cooked great.
Really spiced and seasoned.
Love it.
JACOB:
I wanted to do lunch,
and I didn't want to do
the same thing we do for dinner.
That's how I came up
with deep-fried coconut bake.
That's a traditional word
from Trinidad.
We fry our dough
and we call it bake.
It's infused with the coconut
milk and the coconut flakes.
Makes it feel like you're
in the Caribbean.
Salad, a little dressing,
and then we put the pork in.
This is my Geera pork --
the coconut bake sandwich.
Coconut bread is heavenly food.
It's soft on the inside,
just kind of wants
to melt in your mouth.
MAN:
It's got a crisp to it,
but it's still spongy
and absorbs all the flavor.
It is just an excellent
complement.
JACOB: I get people
from Europe, England.
The world knows about me.
If I lived here in this area,
I'd be here once a week.
I mean, it's simple, it's basic,
it's got great flavor,
there's good depth,
I think it's a good value.
It's the most beautiful gift
that I could have ever received.
You're great.
You are one great cook.
I got to tell you,
I am so proud of Pam
in taking her joint
to the next level.
Now, talking about going to
the next level,
let's talk about a joint
north of Chicago.
I give this place a 10.
When I got there, I didn't know
if it was a diner,
a drive-in, or a dive.
Let's just call it a shanty,
alright?
You tell me.
So, back in 2010,
we're on Route 41
between Chicago and Milwaukee.
I didn't know what to call
this place.
Nah, maybe we wouldn't
call it a joint.
Call it a dive.
Nah, I wouldn't call it a dive.
Well, that doesn't even matter
because the story
got even bigger.
You see, one of our researchers
for "Triple D"
ended up marrying
one of the owners.
This is The Shanty.
♪♪
Whiskey shrimp, table 4.
After I saw The Shanty
on "Triple D", I made the trek,
and I've been coming here
ever since.
You can get any kind of dish
you want.
I've got a shrimp
and scallops sauté.
Thank you.
It's a family-run business,
and it's a great place to eat.
FIERI: It may be family-run,
but when I first got there,
owner Dimitri Kallianis
made it clear
who was really in charge.
So you built a whole menu
off of what
your customers wanted.
Yeah.
Did you let them
set the pricing, too?
Yeah, in a way,
we did.
Really?
'Cause when we raised it,
they yelled,
so then we brought it
back down.
Alligator tail,
table 14.
Now, some of the hot ticket
items were crab cakes
and walleye,
but I dove into this bad boy.
Whiskey shrimp dinner.
We're gonna start off
with some sweet cream butter,
two pitchers of heavy
whipping cream.
In case everybody at home
measures by pitcher.
Three squirts
of yellow mustard.
Pitchers and squirts.
This is jumbo white gulf
shrimp from Texas.
We're gonna add
some whiskey.
This is gonna
flare pretty good.
I like to call this
Greek Lightning.
-Ooh.
-Whiskey sauce,
fresh tarragon,
and there you go.
That's some sauce.
God, the shrimp
are killer.
There's nothing that shrimp
like better
than garlic and butter
and some tarragon.
Whoo.
Good job, man.
Thank you.
Can we have a short rib?
Guy did an unbelievable job
of really coaching me
in the kitchen,
explaining to me
what was coming,
making sure we're
getting more staff,
more kitchen staff,
more parking.
FIERI:
And did they ever.
They quadrupled the size
of their 2,000 square foot
roadside shanty.
This place is enormous.
KALLIANIS: After "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives",
the whole place blew up
with people
coming from all
over the country,
so had to expand
our restaurant.
We added a dining room,
a 100-seat bar area,
outside seating,
wine cellar room.
I mean, really creating
this culinary experience.
4 -- muscles, lemon, wine.
In 11 years, we've changed
our menu 13 times,
constantly reinventing ourselves
and pushing the bar
as high as we can.
Our apple brandy braised pork
shanks are served
as an appetizer or a dinner.
We created an apple brandy
cranberry sauce.
It has a very sweet flavor,
very tangy flavor.
The sweet comes from
brandy-soaked cranberries,
the tangy comes from
the aged balsamic reduction,
and the apple cider vinegar.
We add those to
the natural pork shank,
we braise them
very slow and low.
From there, we take them
and pan sear them,
then we add our sauce
back into the dish,
reducing it with
some aged balsamic.
The meat is very tender.
It'll fall off the bone.
It is just a perfect combination
of savory and sweet.
Hi, there.
We've got a goat cheese wanton.
Thank you very much.
FIERI:
They're also dishing out goat
cheese and basil stuffed wantons
topped with Dimitri's signature
sweet chili sauce
infused with pineapple juice.
Then they're served with
this wasabi cream
to really pack a punch.
WOMAN: I love that it's got
the crispy shell.
They've got the really
sweet pink sauce
combined with the spicy wasabi,
so it's kind of a perfect
combination of flavors.
FIERI: So, going back to
The Shanty was really cool.
I wanted to see how
the restaurant had grown.
the family had changed.
But I got to tell you, this is
way more than I'd expected.
We got a call from
Food Network's
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives",
from a research producer.
I was vetting restaurants
between Milwaukee and Chicago.
We just hit it off,
she seemed very nice,
and from there,
we just kept talking.
We ended up getting married,
and we have two children now.
Looking back, I still
can't believe how life
has it's way of bringing
two people together,
and I am so grateful to "Diners"
for this awesome Greek family.
Wow.
Days of my Greek family.
That's gonna be
a new soap opera.
So, was it a diner, was it
a drive-in, or was it a dive?
Or was it even a shanty?
To me, it looks like
a palace now.
Alright, coming up in Denver,
a joint with a true
identity crisis.
You have got to make some sense
of what's going on here.
So, back in 2013,
I'm in Denver, Colorado.
I go to this joint that's got
a complete identity crisis.
It's a dive bar
with a pizza joint
and a biscuit place
all under one roof.
Sounds crazy,
but it was actually genius.
And now they've got four
locations throughout the state.
This is the one
and only Atomic Cowboy.
Alright, table 4,
an Elmer, DBC Club.
We saw this place on "Triple D",
and we couldn't wait to try it.
WOMAN: The Denver Biscuit
Company, Fat Sully's,
and this whole group
of restaurants here is amazing.
-The slices!
-Whoo!
-Whoo.
-Yeah.
-Look at this.
-Something for everybody.
FIERI: So, when I first walked
into this joint, right away,
owner Drew Shader
had some explaining to do.
You have got to make some sense
of what's going on here.
You've got a bar,
a pizza joint, a biscuit joint,
and you have two food trucks.
SHADER:
Out of the same building.
I've seen some crazy stuff
across the country.
That might just
take the cake.
It is crazy.
SHADER: Whoever was talking
to me for the three weeks
leading up to "Triple D's"
coming
was just talking about
Denver Biscuit Company.
And I was like, "Yeah, Denver
Biscuit Company's amazing,
but the real story here
is that we have three businesses
operating under one roof."
FIERI: We went in just to
check out the biscuits.
Whilst I'm trying the biscuits,
I look over and I see
this pizza joint.
I'm like, "I got to
try some pizza."
So, what size
pizzas do we make?
We do a 26-inch
for slices.
[ Whistles ]
That's a big pie.
Yeah.
It's like a bed sheet.
Look.
[ Laughs ]
So, people come in
and get a slice,
they can get it
any way they want it?
Any way they want.
How much cheese is gonna go
on a pizza this size?
About 1 pound
and 4 ounces.
I'm not gonna
weigh it down.
'Cause you're living
on the edge.
I'm living on the edge.
I got an idea for a pizza.
Let's do some sausage,
some banana peppers,
some artichoke, some basil.
That's where the manhole cover
from Flavortown comes from.
[ Humming ominously ]
SHADER: People absolutely
come in and order...
Sorry.
...the Guy Slice.
It's definitely a top seller.
That crust
is righteous.
Could you hear it?
[ Crunching ]
I'll tell you this, that's not
only the biggest pizza
we've ever shot
on "Triple D",
I honestly got to say
it's one of the best pizzas.
It validates everything
you've done.
MAN: We did see this on
"Triple D", originally.
I enjoyed everything
that Guy recommended.
FIERI:
And now, Fat Sully's is going
above and beyond just the pie.
We've known that if we're
gonna do an entrée for Sully's,
it has to live up
to the pizza.
So, what we do with our chicken
Parm is we grind our chicken,
mix it with a ton of different
spices and herbs,
and make a giant
chicken meatball,
and it becomes like
a plate-sized,
flat chicken meatball.
And then, once we fry it,
it's golden brown,
and we dip it in garlic butter.
We top it with our homemade
red sauce
and our homemade mozzarella.
It's really moist and it has
more of a meatball texture
to it,
so it feels really Italian.
BOY:
I like the cheese on it
'cause the cheese goes good
with the meat.
FIERI: But that's not all
they've got going on.
They've managed to make
your average chicken wing
taste like a party chip.
SHADER: We take the wing,
we brine it overnight
in the buttermilk mixture
that we use
for Denver Biscuit Company.
FIERI: Then after the fryer,
they're dusted with
a custom ranch seasoning
spiked with garlic salt,
onion, and cheese powder.
SHADER: It's tangy, it's sweet,
it's salty, savory,
it's just something
we hadn't seen before.
I love the dry wing.
It's not hot or spicy,
but it's got this great,
rounded flavor to it.
The spicing is really nice.
It's not overbearing.
It's just a really nice wing.
FIERI: But, of course, we can't
forget what brought us here
in the first place --
those biscuits.
♪♪
Holy biscuit mania.
Look at the size of this thing.
Watch, I can hide behind it.
Didn't even know I was there,
did you?
And those biscuits are built
into sandwiches...
Wow.
...like this one,
called the Beeler.
It's their fried chicken dunked
into a Nashville hot glaze
that's basically bacon fat
infused with cayenne pepper.
Beeler on table 6.
The fried chicken was amazing.
It was hot and moist.
MAN:
You have a creamy texture along
with the flavor of the biscuit,
and then you have that little
zing of spice from the chicken.
This is what people
will wish for in their town.
I want an Atomic Cowboy.
Awesome.
You better get ready.
MAN #2: It was a little
hole in the wall
on the corner of something
and somewhere on Colfax,
and it's pretty amazing that
from those beginnings,
it's now five or six stories,
so it's pretty sweet.
SHADER: Things definitely have
changed since that episode,
and I think we'll always
look back on it and say,
"This was a moment
that really propelled us
to a different level."
So, there you have it.
Pam's got a new location,
The Shanty's now a palace,
and Atomic Cowboy --
well, you can find it
just about anywhere,
and that's all 'cause of you
in "Triple D Nation".
See what I'm
talking about, man?
There when the fat
comes to the top.
We're gonna cook it down
until it's nice and tender.
That's when it's done.
You know what
I'm saying, man?
Right up there!
[ Both laugh ]