Hey everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rollin' out.
Looking for America's greatest
Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives.
This trip...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
...It's a West Coast...
That's pretty.
...East Coast...
When in Rome.
Extravaganza.
You've arrived
at Flavor Town.
That means colossal
comfort in Carolina.
Nothin' wrong with that.
Prime time Puerto Rican
in Oakland.
Get after it.
Plus a tasty California cookin'.
Nice little wango tango.
Fired up, fresh, funky,
and full of flavor.
I'd eat here every day.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and" Dives.
♪♪
I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina,
and do I got a doozy for ya.
A dude that's an engineer,
and he's not a chef,
decides to buy a bakery.
Oh, it gets weirder.
Then he says, "Well
I've got the bakery,
I might as well open
for lunch."
Well, the dude that's an
engineer, that's not a chef,
that opens for lunch says, "I'm
gonna open up for breakfast.
And opening for breakfast
isn't difficult enough,
why don't I open for dinner?
And to make it the
perfect trifecta,
I'll just triple the space."
This, is Sweet N Savory.
How's that Chipino workin',
Pete?
It's working hard.
Two minutes.
MAN: Sweet N Savory, is anytime
you want a good meal.
This is my fourth
time this week, so... [ Laughs ]
Salmon Benedict.
Breakfast, lunch, and dinner,
it's hard to choose
when to come.
It's like an emporium.
It's part bakery, part bar,
part restaurant.
Well, we try to be, kind
of everything to everyone.
FIERI: That can do mentality
is the M.O.,
since owner Rob Shapiro
took over this spot
that first opened in 1994.
We started with doing
the basic things well.
Like their most
popular breakfast dish.
SERVER: Your Wrightsville
Beach French Toast.
I've never has a french toast
like this anywhere else before.
It's made with
homemade raisin bread.
It's so decadently delicious.
So what're we
gonna make today?
Cinnamon raisin bread.
Make it happen Cap'n.
First up flour, the salt.
Salt.
Then we got yeast.
Yeast. A bunch of it.
Some sugar.
We'll put in our raisins,
olive oil, water.
And...
We have a starter.
Oh, that smells like
a pitcher of old beer.
How long's this gonna mix?
15 minutes.
And one of his bakery masters
takes it from here.
What's up, boss.
How are ya?
Gonna add a little bit
of my cinnamon sugar,
a little bit more
raisins in here.
Roll it into itself.
And then we got the cinnamon
smear we're gonna put on there.
All right,
let's see the smear.
Pound of margarine here,
let me get some sugar in here,
so I can cream this out.
Flour.
So this'll keep it
together a little bit?
Yes, sir.
Add a little bit
of cocoa powder,
some cinnamon, oil and
water combination in.
Throw it right on
in there like that.
Take a little smear.
The hands peak.
Gotta make sure you can feel
all those nooks and crannies.
Let it proof 25 minutes
in the oven
at 375 for about 46 minutes.
Not 45?
Not 47.
46.
Yes, sir.
We let it rest.
For the French toast,
we usually like to use bread
that's a day or two old,
because it sucks up
a lot more
of the batter.
Look at that
beautiful loaf.
We're gonna start
the batter here.
Whole eggs, whole milk,
some heavy cream,
fresh Vermont maple syrup,
right into the batter.
Cinnamon flavored rum.
Nothin' wrong with that.
Then we put some more
cinnamon in here, too.
Take some of our bread.
Oh, it smells awesome.
Nothin' like
fresh baked bread.
Let it soak up the batter.
Drop them in the deep fryer.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait a second.
They don't want
a flat top?
No.
I'm telling you,
it's too hot in here.
These ovens are starting
to get to you, homes.
You batter 'em up,
and then you fry 'em?
Exactly.
Fried french toast.
And we have
our whipped cream
with Vermont maple syrup
added into it.
A couple strawberries here,
and some fresh blueberries.
Oh, that'll
make it better.
Then you finish it with
some powdered sugar.
♪♪
[ Chuckles ]
That's dynamite.
I mean this is the
french toast that when you
bite into it,
it's creamy all the way through.
And I like how you put
a little bit of the syrup
inside
of the whipped cream.
The texture on the outside,
is so much
like you're
just having a donut.
Exactly.
That's the real
deal right there.
I mean that's real deal.
Order up, french toast.
It's unbelievable.
It's just hard to beat.
I got a beer battered chicken
sandwich, and a chipino.
You walk through the door,
you've arrived at Flavor Town.
You've arrived
at Flavor Town.
It's kind of cool,
and funky, and crazy.
Has the best bakery in town.
We have cinnamon raisin,
rye, and multi-grain.
The bread here is always
really, really good.
FIERI' And it's a vehicle
for this meal,
that really delivers
on the restaurants name.
I have the meatloaf sandwich.
MAN: The meatloaf
is sweet and savory.
It's sweet with the tomato jam,
and with the candied bacon,
and it's savory with the
meatloaf and everything else.
FIERI: So you're known
for your meatloaf.
It's not on both our lunch,
and our dinner menu.
So let's get started.
We're startin' with
some ground veal,
then we have ground beef,
chuck, and brisket,
ground pork, and some
panko bread crumbs.
Okay.
Worcestershire sauce,
eggs up next.
Red and green peppers,
yellow and sweet onion,
salt, pepper, garlic
powder, onion powder.
Then our Italian blend, basil,
oregano, thyme, rosemary.
Brown sugar.
We're running out of stuff
in the shop, buddy.
It can't be meatloaf
without ketchup.
Right in to it.
Blend it together.
The key here is gonna be
not to mix this up too much.
It's gonna be tough,
it'll press all your fat out.
We'll cook that in the baking
oven for an hour and a half,
and then we'll put
a ton of glaze on.
What in this glaze?
Worcestershire, brown sugar,
and ketchup.
And then we let it bake it
for about another half hour
to let that glaze
fully caramelize.
Okay, let's bring
our meatloaf up here.
That's gorgeous.
I'm just gonna get
this on the flat top.
This is our white bread
that we make in house here.
Whoa!
We're gonna start
with house dijonaise.
We're gonna get
our meatloaf on.
Arugula, our tomato jam.
Mini heirloom tomatoes,
fresh rosemary,
apple cider vinegar,
some sugar.
Got it.
And our onion straws,
then we get out candied,
smoked bacon,
cooked in syrup.
You just coat it in
the syrup like that?
Yeah.
When in Rome.
♪♪
The meatloaf and the glaze,
is spot on.
Tender is an
understatement.
The bread's dynamite,
love the arugula in it,
love the straws.
That's a great
meatloaf sandwich.
Maybe bigger though.
Bigger?
Yeah. You still got that much
room left in the ceiling.
Meatloaf in the window.
This is just, mmm.
It's good.
I get a chance to see
some good friends
when I travel around
doing Triple D.
This is my buddy Luis,
from Santa Rosa,
who served our country
in the Marines.
Now lives out here in
North Carolina with his family.
What do you think of
that meatloaf sandwich?
It's fantastic.
The flavor's incredible.
Just the layering of all
the different ingredients.
That bacon?
Phenomenal.
Order up, shrimp and grits.
Pulled pork enchilada.
I've lived here in
Wilmington 20 years,
and Sweet N Savory just keeps
getting better and better.
And it's all done
scratch made.
I mean, it's great.
Really good.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
FIERI: Up next, a Puerto Rican
party spot in Oakland.
Whoa!
FIERI: Courtesy
of an ex-MMA fighter.
Did I tell you how good you
look in that red jacket, sir?
[ Laughs ]
Delivering a knockout
in the kitchen.
Watch out
for this guy, huh?
See?
Is there any on there?
No, you did incredibly
well on that one.
Yeah. I can feel it
running gown my face.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So I'm here
in Oakland, California.
You got great people,
and you got great food.
You have to look
for it sometimes.
I'm here on the outskirts
of Jack London Square,
right under the 880 overpass.
But listen,
this place is worth it.
The chef's serving up some of my
favorite food, Puerto Rican.
You gotta check it out,
here at W.E.P.A Brix 581.
♪♪
Chuleta, roco nanule
with maduro.
This is where I always come,
for Puerto Rica food.
Just bring it back
with bacalaitos.
You can tell it's authentic.
FIERI: And it's all cooked up
by Eric Rivera,
a former bruiser, who decided
to mix it up a little.
I was doin' a little
cage fightin'.
Like MMA?
MMA.
Did I tell you how good you
look in that red jacket, sir?
[ Laughs ]
I would go through my training,
I would miss my food.
I just wanted my favorite
things growing up.
When I stopped
the fighting,
I finally was just like,
"I wanna cook."
I got that pique, and make
sure they know it's hot.
Everything has been, magnifique.
From their chicharrones,
to the mofongo.
Mofongo is made of plantains
and friend chicken.
It is absolutely delicious.
What we're gonna do is,
a chicken chicharron mofongo.
Mofongo's mofongo.
We're talkin' a
fried green plantain.
But the thing that
was interesting,
the chicken chicharron.
Chicken chicharron.
Yeah.
Typically with the pork,
you go all skin.
This, I cut a little
bit more into the meat.
Let's see it,
let's just get into it.
Right now,
we're gonna do a sofrito.
Garlic peels, onions,
green peppers,
the sweet mini peppers.
And a bunch of cilantro.
And then.
And here's the deal, I've got
one of my favorite chefs
from the Bay Area,
Chris Cosentino,
cooks anything
out of everything.
I'm gonna bring him.
I gotcha.
Okay?
He's a little crazy.
That's cool.
I'm crazy, too.
[ Laughs ]
You don't eat a lot
of Puerto Rican food?
I love Puerto Rican food.
In Puerto Rico we've got
a thing called Mayu Ketchup.
Minced garlic,
drop in some onions, the mayo.
The sofrito?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Pepper, cayenne,
granulated garlic,
adobo, Cajun seasoning,
ketchup.
Okay.
This goes on everything.
You could put this
on your cereal.
It's like Puerto Rican
remoulade sauce.
It is actually
Puerto Rican remoulade.
All right,
what are we into?
We're gonna season the
chicken thighs and fat
for the chicken
chicharron.
A little olive oil,
chicken base, Cajun.
Granulated Garlic.
Adobo, pepper.
The season salt.
In the fryer.
Yup.
And next we hit
the plantains.
Yes.
Fry it once, let it cool,
fry it again.
When it comes out,
mold it.
So this is a pilon.
Grease this up
a little bit.
Minced garlic, some more Cajun,
granulated garlic.
And that adobo again.
Yup.
Pepper, plantains.
Get after it.
And we're gonna drop
some chicharron.
Now we're gonna smash it.
And what
was this pilon for?
It's for portion control.
Whoa! Beautiful.
I'm gonna grab these --
This is enough to
feed a family of six.
I wanna feed you
like my momma feed me.
This is the sauce.
And that's the
chicharron mofongo.
♪♪
Good moisture.
I love that you incorporate
the chicharron inside of it.
I want that salty,
crunchy contrast.
And that's
what I'm getting.
You've taken ingredients
that are very humble,
and you've put so
much work into them,
to make them sing.
If there every is bleached hair
in your vision,
you're not taking my job.
[ Laughing ]
Thanks for coming today.
It's been great.
How're you doing guys?
Chicharron mofongo here.
It's a mound of tastiness.
Chicken chicharrones are crispy,
they're really moist inside.
You would not expect
this type of food at a bar.
This is not a restaurant,
it's a bar.
It's a bar-restaurant.
It was Brix 581, and
then when I came aboard,
I decided to change the name,
to W.E.P.A.
Wepa's a term that Puerto Ricans
scream all the time
and say right on
or congratulations.
Wepa! Wepa!
Wepa?
Wepa.
Turned into an acronym.
Wepa means,
where everybody parties at.
WOMAN: If you come late night,
it's not bar food.
It's still Puerto Rican food.
Beef canoa up.
MAN: The canoa's amazing.
Sweet plantain,
the beef has
so much seasoning to it.
Throw the cheese,
and his amazing sauce on there,
and there's not doubt what
I'm ordering when I come here.
What are we into?
So we're gonna prepare
the pecadillo meat,
the Angus beef
and put inside our canoa.
A canoa is a canoe that
is filled with something.
All right,
so give it to us chef.
All right, we're gonna take
our Worcestershire sauce.
What was that called?
I can't pronounce it.
It's what?
No one can.
The sazon, sofrito,
love that Cajun,
the adobo, pepper.
Salt or pepper?
Pepper.
'Cause their an effect.
Yeah, y'all.
Push it.
Granulated garlic,
beef base.
Beef base, okay.
We have beef tenderizer.
Just like mixing meatballs.
Just Puerto Rican style.
Season up the pan,
olive oil, butter in.
The peppers, minced garlic,
and onion, tomato sauce,
Chef, where'd you
steal that pot from?
Yo, let's see.
That's outta your home.
Don't you tell me
that's not outta your home.
It's straight
out the house.
[ Laughter ]
It's my favorite pot!
Drop that beef in there.
You gotta love this guy.
And last but no least,
manzanilla olives.
Then we're gonna grab our
sweet plantain, drop it in.
Okay.
Grab our pecadillo.
It's like a Puerto Rican
version of a hot dog.
It's a chili dog.
Put this in the oven, let
it sit for a couple minutes.
[ Laughs ]
Okay.
Plate it here.
Nice.
It's my remoulade sauce.
Wow.
This moment is really
starting to remind me
of Lady and the Tramp.
We're sharing something,
going towards the middle.
You get the sweet,
the savory, the salty,
the little olive kicker.
I see why you
like the olives.
It really
balances it out.
It's not something you can
really explain real easy.
No.
I love the
cheese on it though.
The way the meat it cooked,
it has a nice mouth feel.
That balances well
with that creaminess.
And it all comes
together under something
as simple
as the plantain.
And it's delicious.
Thank you.
Our beef canoa.
I don't know what kind of
magical unicorn dust
they're putting in here,
but it is amazing.
House special,
chicharron mofongo up.
WOMAN: If you're lookin' for
some Puerto Rican food,
and you're in downtown Oakland,
look for W.E.P.A.
Great job.
Beautiful food.
Thank you.
Nice to have you, Chef.
Thank you, Guy.
Watch out for this guy,
huh?
Adios.
FIERI: Comin' up, we're cruising
just south of Palo Alto.
I'm here to learn.
Where a chef who once
cooked for celebs...
You're a talent, man.
...Is now feeding the masses,
with his rockstar recipes.
It is just a gift.
♪♪
So I'm here in
Palo Alto, California,
about 35 minutes
south of San Francisco.
And I know what you're saying.
"Oh he's there because
it's the center
of the Silicone Valley."
Nope.
"Oh it's because of Stanford."
No, I'm actually here at the
Town and Country Shopping Center
to check out a joint where
this chef has done everything
from cook for Google,
and rock stars,
and now he's opened
his own joint
where he's cooking
California cuisine
his own style, his own way.
This is Calafia Cafe
& Market A Go-Go.
♪♪
AYERS: Dragon's breath
in the window.
Everything's fresh,
it's local,
it's Charlie's style.
Pork bowl in the window.
MAN: People are talking
about Charlie.
Everybody knows Charlie's story.
FIERI: And here's the scoop.
I first met Chef Charlie Ayers
when he competed on
"Guy's Grocery Games."
And he's fed
some American icons,
from the Grateful Dead,
to the wizards of the web.
He was the original
chef at Google.
I was employee number 53.
Really?
Yup.
So I made
a very eclectic menu.
It was a lot Indian food,
vegetarian food,
Southwestern,
a lot of California cuisine.
And then I eventually
opened this.
Chicken curry, table 21.
There's so much
to choose from.
There's a portion
of it for plant eaters,
and a portion for meat eaters.
Fiery bottom pork bowl.
I'm having the fiery bottom
pork bowl.
It's brown rice, green
vegetables, yams, and of course
a big stack of pork on tope.
We're making a fiery bottom
barbecue pork bowl today.
So we're gonna make up
my house made ketchup.
'Cause I don't trust
the manufacturers.
'Cause you don't
trust the man.
Again, man, I'm tellin' ya,
you're an old soul.
So we start with
distilled water,
organic tomato paste,
organic brown sugar next,
organic honey.
Apple cider vinegar.
Garlic powder, ground cinnamon,
cayenne pepper,
ground all spice, whole
clove, and kosher salt.
How long are we gonna
let this cook down?
About an hour, hour and a half.
All right, chef.
Next up.
We're making
my own hot sauce.
Make your own hot sauce?
Make my own hot sauce.
We start again
with distilled water,
organic tomato paste,
lime juice.
Organic.
Organic orange juice,
cider vinegar, tamarind paste.
Nice little wango tango
from tamarind.
Ginger.
Red wine.
Fish sauce.
Fish sauce?
Worcestershire sauce.
[ Mumbles ] sauce
Yeah,
everyone's favorite.
Coriander seeds,
brown sugar, habaneros.
Okay, that's just a
little bit of heat.
Jalapenos, chipotles.
Now we're pickin' up
the heat.
Cumin, carrots,
celery, onion.
Okay, let that cook down,
puree it.
Strain it, and all
this to our ketchup
to make our
barbecue sauce.
Last thing we've got,
is the pork butt.
So we start with ginger powder,
cumin, kosher salt,
bay leaf,
and chili powder.
You're gonna sit with this
dry rub for awhile, or?
Overnight.
Then you're gonna sear it.
I like to use grape seed oil
when I'm cooking.
We want to sear
our meat off.
I like that bay leaf crumble
that you did on that.
Onions, orange.
Are we on like
our tenth dish now,
or is this just one dish
that's taking forever?
Bay leaf, garlic.
And some good ol' beer
from San Fran.
Finish it on the stove top
for two and a half hours.
All right, buddy.
Get it done.
We're gonna pull it, and we're
gonna add some sauce to it,
and we're gonna plate it.
Got some nice steamed
organic brown rice.
This dish works well
over quinoa as well.
Love the Quinoa.
Sauteed spinach
and roasted yams.
Yams he said.
And then we finish
this with our
fiery bottom barbecue pork.
That's pretty.
Get all the goods together.
♪♪
Brother, that's great.
There's a little
heat in there.
The real kicker,
is that sweet potato.
That's what cuts it.
You've got, something
nice and sweet,
which everybody's
looking for somewhere.
Got a health starch.
Got a great green.
Got a lot of flavors
that people like.
Super flavorful, nutritious,
Really good Chef.
I need a pork bowl.
I really like the yams
and the spinach.
The barbecue sauce is sweet
with a little bit
of kick at the end.
And there is a taste
of the south here in that pork.
This is where you go for it,
right there?
Where else could you go?
You can tell how
fresh everything is.
MAN:
Humanly raised meats.
You've got gluten free
if you need it.
Vegan if you want it.
But see, as soon as you say
healthy, [imitating buzzer]
But it tastes amazing.
Vegan love plate in the window.
It's a dish you would order
if you love vegetables.
AYERS: So this is our roasted
vegan love plate.
Love plate.
We start off
with a cauliflower steak.
We have
a romesco sauce here.
Roasted beets.
Gorgeous.
Brussels sprouts.
And then we finish
this with a salsa verde.
What's in the salsa verde?
Garlic, olive oil,
champagne vinegar, parsley.
And then some nice
local micro greens.
You're killing me with the
tweezers, you know that?
I know.
[ Laughs ]
That's it.
Now you think I'm gonna eat
that with a fork and knife?
There you go, that's
the right way to do it.
Mmm.
Delicious.
All the veggies
are roasted perfect.
You're seasoning
is spot on.
Nice bounty
of the county.
You're killin' it.
MAN: It's a really nice plate.
The roasted beets
are really tender.
The carrots are nice
and crisp, very fresh.
I love the little bit
of char on the cauliflower.
It just brings out
the flavor really well.
Well,
I'm gonna finish this.
When we come back, we'll break
into some other kind of jam.
Gnocchi in the window,
pickup.
You guys have to try this.
This is so good.
This is one of the best
things on the menu.
I know this guy, cooks
for Google, cooks for the Dead?
Now he cooks for the triple D.
We'll be right back.
Wow.
I'm getting full.
Welcome back.
we're hanging out at Calafia
in Palo Alto, California,
not too far from
Stanford University, with
the one and only Chef Ayers.
This organic dude from the
East Coast, that hung out
with the Dead, that's got a
million stories to tell ya.
You're like this
culinary Obi-Wan Kenobi.
Charlie has his own style.
Healthy, good quality food.
Gnocchi kale on the window.
Having the gnocchi and kale --
It's one of Charlie's
famous dishes.
It's absolutely delicious.
This is not the way I
typically start my gnocchi,
with a potato
and a tray of salt.
But I'm here to learn.
AYERS: We bake our potatoes
on rock salt.
I find that it really
conducts the heat better,
and gives it
a better flavor
Okay.
So we're gonna bake these
in the oven around 375,
for about an hour,
hour and a half.
On this salt bed?
Yes.
Take 'em out, while
they're still hot.
Peel 'em back.
So I think that salt's
really pulling a bunch
of your moisture out.
That's great.
Makes it a much easier
potato to work with.
Totally.
Everybody loves
mashed potatoes.
Food mill, or a ricer.
Just try it.
That light little fluffy
mixture that he's got,
is the greatest
thing to work form.
Look at this.
Pillows.
I'd eat here every day.
Little salt, some ground pepper,
and some flour.
Touch of olive oil.
And the key is, to not
overwork the mashed potato,
and make it all
glutenous and gummy.
Gummy. Now we're ready
to roll this out.
Okay.
So what I like to do,
is I freeze them.
Freeze 'em?
Drop it frozen.
I feel that starches amalgamate
better with the potato.
Add our grape seed oil
to our gnocchi.
So Brussels sprouts
off the mandolin.
I love Brussels sprouts.
Get a nice color on,
all around.
A little salt and
pepper to that.
All right, add
the kale in there.
I mean, it's very simple food.
Boy did it pack the flavor.
Small amount of garlic.
A little bit of the water
from cooking the pasta.
Got it.
A little chili flake,
some crushed California walnuts.
Oh, my gosh.
♪♪
Mmm. The gnocchi's like
clouds, little puffs.
The walnut is such a surprising,
great texture in there.
It's so good, I could even
have it without the gnocchi.
Straight forward simple,
but done in balance.
It's over the top good.
Punch it.
Thank you.
SERVER: Kale gnocchi.
It's just absolutely
delicious.
It's not heavy like
gnocchi's I've had.
I melts in your mouth,
buttery, never too firm.
Mahogany salmon
in the window.
For organic farm to table,
this is amazing.
We've got a zillion places
within a mile of my house.
But this is where I go.
FIERI: If this was within 15
minutes of my house,
I'd eat here at least three
or four times a week.
I mean,
it is just a gift.
You've a talent man.
Thank you.
I'm gonna see you
back at triple D.
I hope so.
So that wraps
this addition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins,
and" Dives.
If you wanna get some of the
recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next week,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
You can't sound any cooler,
than when you're
from the East Coast.
You go, "It's a little raw."
So you wanna make sure...
Sure.
Wicked.
Wicked sure.
Wicked sure it's raw.
[ Laughter ]