Hey there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives.
This trip... Oh!
...we're grabbing
some gangster grub...
Oh, oh, oh, oh.... at bars,
lounges and clubs.
-Good drinkin' food.
There's out-of-bounds
pizza in Baltimore...
Can't go wrong.... hearty
chicken pie in Philly...
Oh, pure love.
...pierogies
in Pennsylvania...
People are going to come
down here looking for these.
...and an over-the-top
dog in K.C.
That's funkalicious.
Plus legit Irish in Buffalo...
Really good.
...and a wild
Missouri roadhouse...
It's organized funk.
...transporting folks
to Mardi Gras.
Way more than I expected.
So belly up,
grab a cold one and dig in.
That's just how we do it.
That's all right here
right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
And Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in
the Northern Liberties
neighborhood of Philadelphia,
about six blocks from
Center City,
to check out a joint.
Now get this: they were
the first to be serving
only locally made
drafts in Philadelphia
and maybe one of the first
in the country.
You think their beer
program is impressive?
Check out their menu.
This is Standard Tap.
♪♪
MAN: This place is known
for phenomenal beer.
I didn't know it
for phenomenal food.
We're talking real food
that takes time to make,
that takes thought.
Grilled octopus in the window.
What do you like more,
the beer selection or the food?
Beer I have first,
and then I come for the food.
♪♪
Exactly how owners William Reed
and Paul Kimport like to eat.
It's more fun to eat in a bar
than it is to drink
in a restaurant,
and that's what our passion is
is great local beer,
great local food.
FIERI: So when they opened
the joint in '99,
they stuck with the beer
and handed the food
over to friend
and chef Carolynn Angle.
How long have you been here?
I've been here for 13 years.
What, did you start here, like,
on an 8th grade field trip
and got lost?
Something like that.
But the concept
isn't lost on Carolynn.
Everything she cooks is so fresh
and local they don't
even print a daily menu.
The menu changes, but they
always have the standards.
A chicken pie in the window.
Always fall back
on the chicken pie.
It's all crust.
It's amazing.
We're making chicken pot pie?
Chicken pie. Not pot pie.
Chicken pie.
Difference is it's not in a pot.
It's molded.
We build it into pastry.
Just season with salt and
pepper, and then we roast them.
Not going to drizzle
them with anything.
We're just going to roast them
right off in their own juices.
In the oven?
In the oven,
400, little over an hour.
♪♪
So the chickens are cool?
Chickens are cool.
So we're going to pick them.
Are we saving the skin?
We're saving the skin.
We're going to save the bones,
and we're going to make
a stock out of it.
No bones.
What, how did this get in there?
That wasn't me.
That was yours.
No, we... I...
Nope, that was yours.
Next step?
We're making the filling
for chicken pie.
Let's hit it.
Get the pan hot, blended oil.
♪♪
Quartered cremini mushrooms.
Chopped garlic.
Then you want to saute these
until they're
completely caramelized.
Add salt and pepper.
That's a pretty hearty dish.
It's good drinking food.
Good drinking food.
We add some fresh sage
and thyme, fresh parsley.
Then you add your mirepoix.
♪♪
Sweat it all down.
And then we add the chicken.
Okay.
And then we add
the chicken stock.
And how long will this cook down
once the stock goes in?
This will take a couple hours.
Just let it reduce.
And at the end of it cooking
down, what are we going to do?
We're going to add a roux,
and then we're going
to slurry it into it.
We're going to just add a little
bit in just to allow it...
So that'll tighten
all the juices up.
Tighten it up,
but not too tight.
Now we're going
to make the pie.
Then we cut the pastry.
♪♪
Ho, ho, ho,
ho, how much...
I wasn't trying to be
Santa Claus there.
How big is the filling
in this thing?
It's a little smaller
than a softball, about that.
Would you like me to get on
the cutting side of this.
That would be great.
Grab the pastry, and you
stretch it over like that,
and then you cinch it.
Just stretch it.
You don't want to
tear the pastry,
but it's nice and sealed.
Take a piece of puff
pastry, put a strip,
and just twist it
and put it right on top.
Doctor, how is
one twisting this?
♪♪
Now, these are baked
to order, or...
We par bake them.
Par bake them, hold them,
fire them off in the oven again.
Does it come with
a gravy or a sauce or...
With a salad, a bed
of salad underneath it
with some mustard vinaigrette.
Some nice little bed of it.
There you go.
I'm dying to see
this inside here.
Oh, it's dreamy and creamy.
♪♪
Yeah, all right.
I don't think most people
would anticipate
putting this on top of a salad,
but you get a nice crunch.
You get that vinaigrette.
If you like chicken pot pie,
and you want more of the crunchy
crust that you have on top,
this is what you want.
That's killer.
Wait until you guys try this.
♪♪
Tell me about
the chicken pie.
It's, like, super savory,
tons of chicken.
It's like a chicken soup with a
great pastry puff outside of it.
MAN:
Lot of depth of flavor.
This is chicken pie
the way it should be.
These guys have been setting
the trend for a long time.
Really?
Yeah.
It's not your average,
you know, corner pub.
You're going to find things
that are slightly unusual.
What are we onto now?
Drum roll?
Octopus.
Oh, really?
You going to give
it out that quick?
Fire it up.
Octopus.
All right.
First, let's add some water.
Then you add Spanish onions,
celery, fresh grapefruit,
oranges,
lemons, garlic,
bay leaf,
fresh thyme and parsley.
We're going to let
this go for a boil.
We're going to
add the octopus.
So the octopus is not going
to get any salting,
no tenderizing, no nothing.
No. It's fresh octopus,
so it doesn't need it.
Got it. We're going to...
We're going to make
a marinade for the octopus.
Start with some garlic,
crushed red pepper.
Ho.
Little bit of celery
seed, fresh parsley.
What's up with
the red chili flake?
Got to get some heat. Got some
fresh thyme and oregano.
Little salt, white pepper,
vinegar, lemon juice,
olive oil blend,
and whisk.
The octopus is
going to go down.
Are we going to cut it
before we drop it in?
We're going to pull it
apart with our hands.
We'll tear it apart.
Now I know you're serious.
Okay. We're done?
We're done.
So how long was this down?
Couple hours.
Just until it's...
I mean, it literally
is fall-apart tender.
Yeah. So you just
tear it apart.
You leave the suckers on
and throw it in there.
Marinade up, and then are we
going to grill it for service?
We're going to
grill it for service.
Caramelize the octopus.
Pretty good?
Ready to rock?
Ready to go.
We goin'.
Just put a little bit
of baby greens,
some arugula and some tatsoi,
and that's
an oregano potato salad.
♪♪
Little bit of olive oil,
little bit of lemon,
lemon wedge,
and some fresh parsley.
That's all she wrote?
That's all she wrote.
♪♪
Mm. That's good.
It's not so cooked down that
it's falling apart or it's dry.
It's dynamite.
Mm. Not enough people
try octopus.
Really nice job.
I don't always order octopus,
but this is phenomenal.
Sometimes you run into a place
where they take
of the suction cups.
I love how they
leave it on here.
It adds a little extra
little crunchiness.
It is truly outstanding.
So this is a normal kind of
joint you find in Philly?
No, it's extraordinary.
It's the anchor of
the neighborhood.
You got to come down
and try Standard Tap.
Out of bounds.
Great beer, killer food.
♪♪
Coming up, a real-deal
Irish pub in Buffalo...
Why not?
...dishing out
local favorites...
I can only probably eat
about 1,000 of those.
...and throwing a curve ball
with crab cakes.
I'm here on the south side
of Buffalo, New York,
and in a predominately
Irish neighborhood.
We've got a great story
about two brothers:
Kevin, or Laus,
as he was known,
was part-owner of this
neighborhood pub.
Unfortunately, in 2002,
he passed away.
Now, no one wanted to see
the pub leave the family,
so his brother,
Pat, a local fireman,
along with his
brother-in-law, took over.
One of the things we love
on "Triple D" is tradition.
Time to check out
Blackthorn Restaurant & Pub.
-Stuffed pepper in the window.
-Chicken wings.
South Buffalo wings
perfectly done.
Plating that steak.
Vegetables coming down.
Irish beer cheddar.
Thank you.
-Beer cheddar soup, fantastic.
-Fried bologna coming up.
-Traditional Buffalo food.
-At a traditional Buffalo joint.
Almost the exact
same since '77.
-So when Pat Lalley...
-How's everything going?
And his brother-in-law
Larry Adymy
took over 4 years ago...
Got the herb.
...they stuck with tradition.
MAN: We tweaked some things,
redid the menu,
but the classics of the
Blackthorn haven't been touched.
FIERI: Like this
local classic...
-Beef on weck.
-...roast beef on
a salt and caraway-topped
kimmelweck roll.
This is what Buffalo
is known for.
The perfect sandwich.
FIERI: And head chef
Max Leatherbarrow...
-Coming up.
-Is cranking out
around 20,000 a year.
What are we going to make?
We're making our roast beef
for the beef on weck sandwich.
Beef on weck.
Well, show me the way we do it.
Start with onions
in the pan, carrot, celery.
So we're making a little
mirepoix, it looks like,
to the bottom of this pan.
Basically, yes.
Then we're going to put the beef
in the pan, Angus round.
Big top round.
Next, I do a browning agent.
Agent Browning?
Agent Browning. Rub that in.
All right. We put a little
Worcestershire on,
Montreal steak seasoning,
pat that down.
And then last we have
some fresh rosemary.
That you grow in your backyard?
Yeah, I brought this from home.
So what's going to happen now?
This is going to go
straight in the oven.
300 degrees, 3 hours.
Are you going for
an internal temperature?
Yeah. I'm looking
for around maybe 110.
So you really coming
out medium rare.
He's ready.
Wow.
There you have it.
Look at that bad boy.
So you let it rest,
when you slice into it,
all the juices don't
come flowing out.
Exactly.
And this is what
we're going to make
the au jus from?
Yeah. I basically put
all the vegetables
and pan drippings into a pot.
We add water, kosher salt,
a little browning agent,
ground black pepper, beef base.
Once the au jus comes to a boil,
we strain it,
and that's your au jus.
That's it. Then we're slice it.
This is our final product.
Then we're going to put this
on weck?
Start with a bun.
Dip the top in au jus,
caraway seed and kosher salt.
I've never seen someone
do it here in location.
I've always seen it
come with it on there.
Why not fresh?
Why not?
All right. Take our beef, let it
dip right in the au jus.
Let it warm up for a minute.
We got the bottom of our bun,
got our beef on there,
top of the bun.
There you have it.
So that's it, beef on weck.
Nice and soaking weck.
Mm, wow. That is so tender.
Big flavor, crazy with
the salt and the caraway.
That au jus is awesome too.
Mm. I can only probably
eat 1,000 of those.
Nice job, man.
-Beef on weck is so delicious.
MAN: The meat is perfect.
It's tender.
There's no grizzle, no nothing.
No schnizzle on the grizzle.
That's how they
say it around here.
-Beef on weck in the window.
-I just love the place.
You're my chicken wings
with ranch, right?
This is our table, actually.
FIERI: And this is where Pat's
firehouse brothers like to sit.
Everyone comes here.
They know it's good food.
Cops and firemen always know
the best place to eat.
-And what to eat.
-Beer cheddar soup.
A nice little kick
to it, very good.
And it's a more-than-30-year-old
Blackthorn recipe.
I see cheese and beer.
We're making some soup.
We're making soup.
This is our Irish beer
cheddar and potato soup.
Start out
with butter, onion.
Let it stir. We're going
to let these sweat.
And what's going to happen now?
We add some Irish beer.
All that beer?
All that beer.
A ton of beer, dude.
Yeah, I've had a lot of
cheddar beer soup before,
but I don't think I've
ever seen that amount.
Let this come to a simmer.
Takes about 10, 15 minutes.
Going to add our potatoes.
This might splash, watch out.
Now these are peeled
and parboiled?
Yes.
How much of this soup
you guys go through a week?
About 20 gallons a week.
So potatoes are in.
We add our seasonings,
white pepper,
Montreal steak...
Montreal seasoning, of course.
Seasoned salt, chicken base.
Stir that in.
Bring this up to a boil.
It's great so far.
All right. Now we're going to
add the cheese,
about a handful at a time.
Shredded cheddar
and Monterey Jack.
And just slowly
whisk that cheese in.
Yeah.
We do it all at once, obviously,
it's going to clump up.
Clump up, and you'll have
the bottom of somebody's fondue.
Exactly.
The cheese is in.
Now what happens?
Heavy cream, and we add
a little nacho cheese sauce
just for color and to...
Thicken it up a little bit.
Sure.
So let that simmer, and then
what do we serve it with?
Side of saltine crackers.
There you go.
Hot sauce if you wish.
Wow. I can smell
the beer like crazy.
Mm, wow. That's big, deep,
rich flavor. Creamy.
Just have, like,
a perfume of the beer.
Mm. That is the most beer I've
ever seen in beer cheddar soup.
We don't mess around
with beer in Buffalo.
No, you don't.
What kind of hot sauce is that?
That's wing sauce.
Mm.
With the hot sauce
in there, really good.
Good job, man.
Thanks.
-Really good job.
-Fantastic.
-Really creamy and cheddary.
-Cheddar soup going out.
Any way you can
put beer in a soup,
I think it tastes yummy.
-Irish beer cheddar.
You can get anything you want
here, and you'd be happy.
FIERI: All the Buffalo favorites
you'd expect...
-Chicken wings.
-Nice and plump and crispy.
...and a few things
you wouldn't.
-Crab cakes.
-Done Baltimore-style.
You don't have to go
to Maryland. They're right here.
Well, give me the rundown, man.
I'm a crab cake aficionado.
Start by running our veg
through a food processor.
Green and red bell pepper,
Spanish onions,
celery, let it spin.
I mix it together just so it
doesn't break down really bad.
How many clicky, clicky,
click, click, click?
Between 12 and 15, I guess.
Yes, very nice.
That goes in the bowl.
Next, we're going to add
our crab meat, eggs.
Six eggs.
A little bit of dill.
Whoa.
Take it easy on that.
Gorilla with the dill-a.
Wow.
Old Bay seasoning,
Greek dressing, our lemon-dill
mayo that we make here.
Going to dill-ify it
one more time.
Sure.
And what was in this?
Lemon juice,
dill and mayonnaise.
Oh, sure. It's lemon juice,
It's a lemon-dill mayo.
How about call it
lemon-dill mayo.
All right. Oh, good idea.
We have some chopped garlic.
Whole mess of that.
Parmesan cheese.
Swiss cheese.
Provolone cheese.
Mix of shredded cheddar
and Monterey Jack.
In the crab cake?
In the crab cake.
And then 4 cups
of bread crumbs.
Well, the only thing
we haven't stuck in there
is the kitchen sink
and your hat.
That's next.
We're going to mix it up.
Now we're just going
to patty these up.
Looking for about
5 1/2, 6 ounces.
There's one of our patties,
flour this,
put a nice crust
on the outside.
And no seasoning in the flour?
Just straight-up all-purpose.
Here's our second one,
flour this up.
And how are we
going to cook these?
On the flat top.
Butter down.
Yeah. So a couple minutes
each side.
Yeah. We're basically trying
to get a nice crust on them,
heat them through.
That's a normal order?
Yes.
All right. Let's serve them up.
These get served
with rice, vegetables.
Hit them with our
lemon-dill mayonnaise.
There you have it.
I want to just try it
without the mayo.
Look in there, you see
crab right off the bat.
It's a good sign.
Mm, great flavor.
Good mixture of crab.
I like the crunchy
veggies in there.
The dill-lemon mayo
couldn't be any better.
The thing that is
the best is that texture.
Look at the crunch
on that right there.
That's a good cake.
Good job, man.
Thanks.
The Maryland crab
cakes, perfect.
Crispy on the outside and nice
and moist on the inside.
The dill sauce really
complements it well.
You had a beer cheddar
as well, right?
Blackthorns is the place to be.
It's a great neighborhood joint.
It really is.
He's a good guy.
-Great service, great people.
-Beef on weck.
I love to see that
you guys are here.
You're doing it, and you
definitely have a presence,
and definitely are taking
care of your community.
I think that's awesome.
-Thanks for coming.
We really appreciate it.
-Oh, we've had a blast.
Up next, after digging
into all that crab,
I gotta head to Baltimore.
Here we go.
But this time, I'm trading in
seafood for a skater joint...
What in the wild, wild world
of sports is going on here.
...rolling out
with a killer pie.
Little funky joint
like this? Dynamite.
♪♪
So I'm here in Upper Fells Point
of Baltimore, Maryland,
just a couple blocks
from the harbor,
where a dude that's a good
skateboard and punk rock fan
has taken an old-school
local bar
and turned it into kind of
like a Neapolitan pizzeria,
except he calls it
a Balti-politan pizzeria.
This is Johnny Rad's.
♪♪
Two orders of
risotto balls up.
Little bit more upscale
as far as the food goes
that you would expect
at a skater joint.
Salted caramel bread pudding.
The vibe here is awesome.
BMX guys, old skate guys,
a lot of tattooers come in here.
FIERI: Which also pretty much
describes Rich Cue,
the dude who started
this joint back in 2010.
Why Johnny Rad's?
It's a name of
a fictional character
in an old skateboard
movie from 1987.
Were you in the restaurant
business before this?
Not at all. I started
making pizza at home.
And taught himself
to master the pie.
Now he's got Chef Grayson Reeder
cranking out his recipes.
I love the pizza here.
There's a lot of vegetarian
options, the Train Wreck.
Got a large Train Wreck,
table six.
It's got olives
and baby spinach.
Marinara sauce,
really crispy dough.
Holy...
What in the wild, wild world
of sports is going on here?
That is huge.
How much dough do you make?
We go through about two
or three batches a day.
Let's get after this.
All right.
First, we're going to put
our water in the bowl.
Next, we're going to add
our secret ingredient,
which is actually cola.
Cola is in.
Now we're going to add
the bloomed yeast,
flour, kosher salt.
Lot of salt.
We're going to let it mix
for about 3 minutes.
All right. So now we're going to
add our extra virgin olive oil.
There you go.
We're going to let that mix
for another 15 minutes.
Now we're going to
come out of the bowl.
Want me to hold the bucket?
There we go.
Get in there.
Seventeen and a half
ounces, correct?
You ever seen
this maneuver?
Yep. Yep.
Look at that, huh?
It's perfect.
Beautiful.
We brush the top
of the dough balls
with extra virgin olive oil.
Those proof 24 hours.
Here we go.
Two ladles of red sauce.
♪♪
That's a very light
amount of sauce.
Yeah. Next goes the spinach.
Little bit of mushroom.
And now we have
black olives.
These are fresh
mozzarella balls.
Little bit of extra
virgin olive oil.
And this is the Train Wreck?
In the oven, 650.
About 6 minutes.
♪♪
Good-looking pie,
smell that yeast.
Now we're going to add
a little bit of salt,
little bit of Asiago cheese,
and we're going to cut it.
And that's all she wrote.
That's all she wrote.
Good-looking crust.
The crust is nice and thin,
light and airy,
not doughy and heavy.
You do get a little bit
of that cola in there.
Right, yeah. Yep.
Get a little bit of that carbol.
But you didn't overdo it
with too much ingredients.
♪♪
Got great balance.
Love the fresh mozzarella.
That's a nice slice.
Can't go wrong.
Little funky joint
like this, dynamite.
Ingredients are really fresh.
I like the crust.
It's nice and chewy
but crispy at the same time.
A good amount of toppings
on it, but not too much.
This is, like,
totally my scene.
There's always
good music playing.
There's good videos on the TV.
Has some cool old video games
over in the side room.
Come here just exclusively
for Skee-Ball.
And then really
good food as well.
You can get burgers.
You can get appetizers
like the risotto balls.
Gooey on the inside,
crispy on the outside,
and the perfect
pre-pizza snack.
All right. Let's get after this.
So we're making risotto balls.
Little bit of canola oil.
Go in with some mushrooms.
Go in with a
little yellow onion.
Veggie seasoning.
Little veggie seasoning.
Little bit of kosher salt.
Little bit of pepper.
Saute that up for
3 or 4 minutes.
We're going to add
our Arborio rice,
let that get a little toasted.
Little white wine.
Whole lot of white wine.
Whole milk.
Let this cook down...
About 15 minutes.
We're going to add
the Caesar blend cheese,
a little heavy cream.
After the risotto cooks
for about 15, 20 minutes,
we add it to a hotel pan
to cool in the walk-in.
There we go.
The white wine
in that, gangster.
You didn't overcook it.
So we're going to scoop, put
a little divot in the center.
Add some cheese.
Little mozzarella
cheese surprise.
Drop it in Italian bread crumb.
How many come with an order?
Six.
I like this.
Risotto balls
are all finished.
And what kind of sauce
we serving them with?
Pizza sauce.
♪♪
It's good risotto
just by itself.
Then you add a little bit
of mozzarella cheese in that.
Lightly fried, not even really
frying, just warming it.
You get that wine
and mushroom flavor
coming through
from the risotto.
Pizza sauce, just a nice,
bright, fresh tomato flavor.
Yeah.
That's a nice simple arancini,
rice ball, whatever you call it.
Thanks, man.
Well done, brother.
The chef makes the risotto
at the perfect al dente,
and so you have this
combination of textures.
Excellent for soaking
up the drinks
that you will be consuming.
You watch Food Network,
you know "Ace of Cake"'s
original Mary here.
What is it about Johnny Rad's
that is so cool?
Great food, great people.
I'm friends with, like,
half of the staff, and it's...
You're friends with
half the country.
Yeah, that's true.
This is like when we were
kids, and you said,
"One day, I'm going to
put up all cool skateboard stuff
and play really awesome music
and make pizza and have beer,
and all my friends
can come over."
I couldn't have said
it better myself.
That's exactly what this is.
It's exactly what this is.
Coming up on this
full hour of "Pub Grub"...
That's Roadhouse eating.
A New Orleans party spot nestled
in Webster Groves, Missouri...
Did your wife just make
you empty your garage?
...serving a barbecue
spaghetti mash-up...
As I shove my mouth full of it.
...and a Cajun spin
on an Asian classic.
You really put some time
and energy into that.
♪♪
So here I am in the beautiful
Webster Groves area
of St. Louis, Missouri, to check
out a joint...
Now, get this.
It started out as a lumberyard.
Well, then it became
a record store.
Then it was a restaurant
a few times.
And now, rumor has it, it's
owned by a fellow UNLV alum.
Oh, they're serving up food
from the blues highway.
We're talking Cajun,
seafood and barbecue.
This is Highway 61 Roadhouse.
♪♪
Smothered catfish, voodoo
shrimp sandwich going up.
WOMAN: Really has that
New Orleans feel and taste,
and stepping into
the Roadhouse
is like stepping into a place
off of Bourbon Street.
Full slab in the window.
You born and raised here?
Born and raised St. Louis.
You've had some
St. Louis barbecue.
I have.
How does that stack up?
It's the best.
It's real deal?
It's real deal.
How you guys doing?
Just what I'd expect from fellow
Running Rebel alum Bill Kunz.
He's been rocking
out the Roadhouse
with his own brand
of party since 2006.
Brother, it is the most funky
eclectic disorganized...
Well, actually, it's organized.
It's organized funk.
Did your wife just make
you empty your garage?
♪♪
Barbecue shrimp dinner,
red beans and rice going up.
So it's the food between
St. Louis and New Orleans?
Yes. Sin City, Vegas,
Sin City, New Orleans.
Nothing parties like
those two cities.
Not that I would know.
This funky approach is showing
up in the sweet potato pie,
smothered pork steak
and this off-the-hook mash-up of
two of my favorite things.
Barbecue spaghetti
dinner in the window.
It's like having
a pulled-pork sandwich
and pasta at the same time.
It's fantastic.
-Barbecue spaghetti?
Barbecued spaghetti.
It's a little sacrilege.
Just look at him.
Feel it. Let's get started.
This is the dry rub
for the pork butt.
Yep. Sea salt,
granulated garlic, paprika,
granulated onion,
raw sugar,
black pepper,
The kitchen sink.
Little cayenne
for heat, chili powder.
And as you always should,
a little dry mustard.
I'll whisk all this together.
♪♪
A couple nice,
big, fat butts.
Mm. Here.
This is what
we're talking about.
Okay, so little ACV.
Apple cider vinegar.
Add a little moisture to it.
How many of these you go through
a week?
About 24 of them a week.
Pulled pork sandwich,
pulled pork dinner,
barbecue sampler.
Sampler?
Sampler.
Boy, that's an '80s term.
We have the super
sampler too, so there.
You didn't say super sampler.
I said super sampler.
Nice generous rub to that.
Mm-hmm.
Into the walk-in?
For half a day.
Then we're going to
the smoker.
What temperature
we going to run this at?
Two twenty-five.
Low and slow for about...
Thirteen hours.
Pull it out.
Look at that.
That's pull-apart tender, huh?
Look at the great bark on that.
See that color?
See that smoke penetration?
But not a ton of smoke.
No, no. Not oversmoked.
It's not burnt on the outside,
just so you know it,
as I shove my mouth full of it.
You'll take the bear claws.
This is where Wolverine
got his idea, by the way.
Just so you know.
He worked in
a barbecue restaurant.
So you'll shred this up.
Mm-hmm.
So nice and juicy,
ton of flavor.
Apple cider vinegar
over it again.
Okay. Little more rub.
And a light dusting of rub.
That's all she wrote.
Next up...
Highway 61 barbecue sauce.
Sea salt, cayenne pepper,
Worcestershire sauce,
little cinnamon,
nutmeg,
chili powder, black pepper,
real tomato ketchup.
Real tomato ketchup,
33 percent fancy.
Mustard.
Apple cider vinegar.
Light brown sugar.
All right, so let this
cook down how long?
About 30 minutes.
So we've got our pulled pork.
We've got our pasta
that's been cooked al dente.
Now where we at?
We're going to take
a little chicken stock.
♪♪
Add our barbecue sauce,
pulled pork.
All right. We're going
to add our pasta.
This just does
not look right.
It isn't.
Oh.
And to top it off
is the fabulous garnish
of chopped parsley.
No, only if you
run it around the rim.
That's Roadhouse eating.
♪♪
Pulled pork is dynamite.
The sauce has got
a nice twang to it.
The vinegar coming through,
great texture of the pork.
This is every bit
a pulled pork sandwich
with pasta injected into it.
I dig it. You get the parsley
garnish, the super sampler.
It's all '80s here, baby.
Awesome.
You're classic, man.
Barbecue spaghetti.
WOMAN: It's unexpected because
you have the barbecue
and a little bit of spicy.
It's delicious.
FIERI:
But that ain't the only way
this joint is spicing things up.
Cajun pot stickers steaming.
It's got andouille sausage in
it, so it gives it a great kick.
Mixed with soy sauce,
great flavor combination.
Unbelievable.
Next up?
Cajun pot stickers.
Ca-Asian? Ca-Asian?
Cajasian,
C-A-J-A-S-I-A-N.
And Bingo was his name.
Fire it up.
Sesame seed oil,
green pepper, celery, onion.
Sweat them?
Sweat them.
Raw andouille sausage.
Where you getting that from?
We're flying it in
from New Orleans.
Seriously?
Yep.
Now we go in with
a little bit of sambal?
Sambal. Crushed red pepper,
sea salt, black pepper.
Everything is going
to get cooked in the fat
coming out of that andouille.
What happens after that?
Put it in a blender.
Break it down even
a little bit more.
Break it a little more.
We got some pot
sticker skins.
Oh!
And we'll stuff
our pot sticker skins.
Little egg wash.
Fold them over.
Once they've had a chance
to kind of set up,
then we take them,
hit them in the skillet?
Hit them in the skillet,
little sesame seed oil.
♪♪
Get the bottoms
nice and crispy,
and then put some chicken stock
in there to steam them.
They're ready.
♪♪
So the dipping sauce
for the Cajun pot stickers?
So make that the centerpiece.
Yes, sir. And scallions.
♪♪
I like that
it's all handmade.
♪♪
That's good sausage.
Very good.
Little bit spicy.
Got a little kick to it, mm-hmm.
You really put some time
and energy into that.
You fly in the sausage.
You make the stuffing yourself.
You hand-make
the pot stickers.
Just a little.
Way more than
I expected, man.
Nice job. Very nice job.
Thank you.
Cajun pot stickers
in the window.
It's an incredible merger
of both Asian and Cajun.
That tastes like New Orleans
in a pot sticker.
Perfect. You come here,
and you're home.
You're happy.
Nothing better.
It does feel like a good
Highway 61 joint, man.
You know what
I always say, go '80s!
Up next, a funky lounge in
Blawnox, Pennsylvania,
cooking up comfort...
That's not what I would
expect to find in a lounge.
...with pasta, peppers and
pierogies. I'm telling you.
That is about simple
goodness right there.
When you're looking for
a great neighborhood bar,
well, you're probably
looking for a place
that's been there for a while.
So here we are
in Blawnox, Pennsylvania,
at the Starlite Lounge,
opened in '54,
and, still today,
a local favorite.
Good place to hang out,
grab a cold beer
and check out some
homemade pierogies.
-They're the best.
-They're so good. Mm.
FIERI: Polish dumplings filled,
boiled and sauteed
in butter and onion.
I think they're fantastic.
-The food is really good.
-Good fresh food.
FIERI: From the pierogies to the
meatloaf, the fish sandwich...
-Here we go....
-Chicken Diablo...
-Couldn't be better.
-And fettuccine Alfredo
with chicken and mushrooms.
I don't even like mushrooms,
and I like this.
It's excellent.
I get it a lot.
Do we really call
this bar food?
I don't.
No, this wouldn't be bar food.
FIERI: But they've got that
if you want it.
Hot wings, buffalo wings,
garlic and buttered wings.
Ronny just cooks up a storm.
FIERI: That'll be Ron Esser,
everyone calls him Moondog,
a former musician who bought the
Starlite almost 14 years ago.
The fellow that sold it
to me insisted
that it would always...
That you would keep the name?
Absolutely.
So he did and amped up the menu
with real home cooking...
Tastes like Momma Lombardi.
...from Lora Mazeski's
grandma...
I got the recipe
from my grandmother.
...for homemade pierogies
folks at this joint
just can't get enough of.
An amazing plate of pierogies.
They're kind of like dumplings
in other, you know,
nationalities.
Polish raviolis.
Order of pierogi.
FIERI:
And when it's pierogi time,
Lora leaves the floor
and heads for the kitchen.
How do we start
with the pierogi?
You need to make the dough.
4 cups flour,
1 cup sour cream,
water, two eggs, stir it all up.
And this is the batter?
Yes.
Then you need to work it
with your hands.
So it's just supposed to be
a sticky blob at the bottom?
Yeah. It's kind of like
dough for a pie.
Oh, I don't know
if there's more left
in the bowl or on your fingers.
I'm a messy cook.
Put this aside and let it rest?
Yeah, for 15 to 20 minutes.
And then we start
working on the filling?
Yep, after I wash
my hands, of course.
Just go ahead and wipe
them on my shirt.
I'm just kidding.
So we just boil
down some taters.
Four to five.
And I'm going to
stick them in my mixer.
American, so we've
got it processed.
It has to be American.
Has to be American?
Yes. Saute one large onion.
And a half a cup of butter?
No, a half a pound.
Half a pound?
Yes.
So we are almost
making the consistency
of mashed potatoes with cheese
and a half pound of butter.
Yeah.
Now we get the dough,
and I flatten it.
Then I just grab
some of this.
You flap it over,
make sure that it's sealed.
Can I try one?
Of course.
All right. So I get a glob
of this mixture,
and I get some more flour
down, little bit more, right?
Yeah.
Am I looking
pretty good at this point?
It looks beautiful. It almost
looks better than mine.
I'm a pierogi apprentice.
Now we get Moondog.
Yo, Moondog.
Now what happens to them now?
We boil them for
about 5 minutes.
Now, what gets served with it?
Butter and onions.
You got to have
a lot of butter.
We'll let them cook.
I think they're ready.
They're enormous.
These are real pierogies.
You brown them.
They're nice and gushy and...
Gushy as a culinary term.
There you go. Look at that.
This is kind of like
what grandma used to make.
♪♪
Mm. I'm telling you,
that is about
simple goodness right there.
People going to come down
here looking for these.
Grandma would be happy?
Yes.
There you got it.
What makes them so good?
-Butter.
-Lots of butter, very good.
It's a pretty popular
Pittsburgh dish.
-Best in the Burgh.
-Best in the Burgh?
That's Pittsburgh?
-It's the best pierogi
I've ever had, actually.
FIERI: Just a little piece
of a menu that's covered all
the bases for years.
He always has a lot of very good
different kinds of food.
Greek fish sandwich.
Since I was a kid,
this place was known
for having a great
fish sandwich.
And Ron makes it
even better.
Things don't have to be
that fancy to be good.
Oh, they have all kinds
of different styles.
It's the best
food around here.
Especially the soup.
Stuffed pepper soup,
tastes like homemade.
FIERI: Because it is.
So the ingredients
of stuffed peppers,
but, instead, you chop it all up
and make soup out of it?
Basically. So we like
to make it fresh.
Serve it up.
Who came up with the recipe?
It originated in 1860 in...
No, I don't know.
Real nice tomato base to it.
On a cold Pittsburgh day,
this would be what
you want to go for.
-Right. Oh, yeah.
-It's real tasty.
One order for you.
This is, like, a sit-down
restaurant.
WOMAN: There's a full menu.
And if you're in the mood for
a burger, wings,
they have pasta.
FIERI: And if all you want
is a salad...
So you got melted cheese
and French fries
on top of a cold salad?
This is the best chicken salad
you ever had in your whole life.
And their French
fries are so good.
Hand-cut and double fried,
the same scratch cooking
that's kept the locals
piling in forever.
MAN: See, I was born
and raised in town,
and so I probably been
coming here 50 years.
MAN: People keep coming back
because it has a home
atmosphere.
Pretty much know
everybody that's here.
And you know you can
count on good food.
If you're going to cook,
you might as well do it, right?
-What do you have?
-Chicken Diablo.
It's quality stuff.
-Who made the recipe?
The devil, I guess.
I don't know. I made it.
This is the cast
of characters?
Some peppers, some onions.
Get the chicken going.
I grow these peppers,
and then I can them.
Yellow peppers.
Just a little bit
of marinara on.
Sriracha.
Do you want
some of that in yours?
Just, yeah, put a little
taste of it in there.
Just cut it up
a little bit, the chicken.
Cut it right on the grill.
Throw it in.
Throw a little
pasta in there.
Mm. Wow, that's a portion, huh?
That's good. Look at that.
Now what, a little
Parmesan cheese on top?
Mm. The pepper
and the chicken
and the spice really
go together great.
Those peppers
are dynamite, man.
All I want to do is find
more of those peppers.
-Spicy, absolutely great.
-Alfredo.
There's not too many places that
you would go even in Pittsburgh
where you'd find these
kind of pasta dishes,
and then you also find wings
and burgers and bar food.
-Thank you.
-And grandma's pierogies.
Homemade pierogies, very good.
They're great.
I'll tell you this, Moondog.
It's not what I would
expect to find at a lounge.
What makes it so good?
Big guy, big portions.
How tall are you?
I'm 6'10".
There's not much of this
right now that I'm enjoying.
Coming up, a rocking music
venue in Kansas City...
That's cool.
...hitting a high note
with their meatloaf...
I like that.
...and headlining a hot dog
bacon deep-fried trio.
I've been all over the country.
I don't think we've
ever seen anybody
adulterate a dog in this form.
So here I am in Kansas City
ion the Crossroads Art District.
Now, does that sound familiar?
Well, it should because
I'm like a block and a half away
from one of our favorite
"Triple D" characters,
Stretch, you know,
and his joint, Grinders.
So what is it about
this neighborhood?
I mean, we're talking music
venue with homemade food
like this joint, The Brick.
♪ Oh, the night is for
the lovers ♪
Came for the music,
stayed for the food.
Meatloaf sandwich,
sweet potato fries.
Best meatloaf ever.
The apple butter
and Brie for you.
Brie and apple butter,
delicious on rye bread.
I don't even
consider it bar food.
She sort of elevates bar
food to a new level.
FIERI: She is former
bartender Sheri Parr.
I cook. I clean.
I book the bands.
Welcome to The Brick.
Sounds like you own the joint.
I own the joint.
Oh, you own the joint.
Since '99...
-Here we go, folks.
...when she started cranking out
bar food her way.
Meatloaf is coming up.
It's better than bar food.
Crunchy Thai chicken salad,
that is super.
Pork tenderloin just to die for.
Oklahoma and Thai.
Oklahoma dog,
they deep-fried the hot dog.
It's wonderful.
What are we making first?
The Oklahoma dog.
We're making the batter.
It's got flour, sugar...
Okay.
Baking powder,
a little salt and one egg.
Mix that together.
With some beer.
Want me to drizzle?
Please.
So what do...
Oh, in there.
Oh, that's good.
Really?
That's a pretty
tight batter, huh?
What are we
going to do with this?
We have a quarter-pound
all-beef hot dog.
Wrap the bacon around them
and then roll it in
the beer batter.
We're going to deep-fry it?
Yes.
-Oh, that is just...
-Toasted sourdough bun.
And then I get
my toothpicks out.
One, two, three.
All right. Oklahoma dog.
Holy schnikey.
This is ridiculous.
Yeah, it is.
Does anything else go on this?
Yeah. We can put some mustard
and some onions on it.
That's how we serve it.
I got to just take a look at it.
So there you are.
You're walking down the street,
and someone says,
"Hey, how about
4,000 calories in a bun?"
Mm.
That's cool.
I've been all over the country.
I don't think we've
ever seen anybody
adulterate a dog in this form.
Super-mega-juicy-hotdog --
that's one word,
wrapped in le bacon,
that's French,
so you know it's good,
crunchified in beer batter,
that's funkalicious.
That, you got to try.
You, bad person.
I need another Oklahoma dog.
Absolutely delicious.
The bacon, I think,
is what sets it off.
It is awesome,
definitely filling.
It's just really, really good.
That's a Brick dish.
FIERI: Which means handmade...
Cuban chicken 4 minutes.
...and classic,
but different.
The pubbie with
sweet potato fries.
The menu is full of them.
Order in.
I need another Oklahoma dog
and another apple butter Brie.
I knew she could cook,
but I didn't know how well.
I got a Brick burger,
a Cuban and a meatloaf down.
It's always got a lot of flair
and spice and flavor.
Cuban chicken sandwich.
You can tell it's all homemade.
You guys really have the time
to do all this kind of stuff?
We make the time. It's important
to us that things taste good.
-Like this heavy hitter.
-Fabulous meatloaf sandwich.
Piece of meatloaf
is just wonderful.
It's better than mom's.
-And scratch-made...
-I got meatloaf.
-Right down to the ketchup.
Chipotle ketchup, killer.
I'm a fan.
We're going to make
chipotle ketchup.
Great.
First, some olive oil.
We saute the onions.
Salt and pepper.
So the onions have sweated?
We add apple cider vinegar,
brown sugar, chipotle pepper,
chipotle pepper sauce.
Which is called...
Five dollar question.
Adobo.
Very nice.
Tomato paste,
Worcestershire, Worcester...
What is the word?
I can cook,
but I can't say that.
Just say Wor...
Wor...
...chesh, chesh, chesh, chesh.
Wor-che, che, che, che, che.
Then we mix this up, and then
we add the pureed tomatoes.
So, no ketchup goes in this.
This is all you just
doing it your way.
Right. We like to do it our way.
Smells great.
Let this sit there and simmer.
An hour, and hour and a half.
Now that it's simmered,
fresh-squeezed lime juice.
Little brightness,
little acid.
Break down the onions.
We're good to go.
I just want to taste
this by itself.
Oh. I like that.
That's good ketchup.
Thank you very much.
And this is
for the meatloaf sandwich?
-Yes.
-Okay. What are we onto?
Meatloaf.
I make it all in the same pan
that I'm going to cook it in.
Seven eggs.
That's a lot
of liquid chicken.
Homemade marinara, onions.
So this is a gigantic
dump and stir.
I love the rye bread.
Haven't seen that one.
Such delicious bread.
Add a little Worcestershire,
parsley, little salt.
Some pepper.
We mix all of this up.
I can get my foot in there
if you need me to.
And then 10 pounds
of ground chuck.
And mix that all up thoroughly,
form the grande loaf,
wrap it in foil, pop it
in the oven, what temperature?
425, about 1 1/2 hour.
Remove the foil...
The last 1/2 hour.
Let it get all nice
and crusty brown on the outside.
Yeah. Okay?
Yeah.
Now that goes on the flat top?
On the flat top.
Will you hand me the oil?
All right.
Hand her thing, takes...
I almost did drop it.
Put this on the flat top.
I let it get kind of
crunchy on both sides.
Dig it.
Bread toasted.
Wheatberry bread.
Pepper Jack cheese, cover it.
Get a little water under there,
melt the cheese.
That's what we're talking about.
Our meatloaf, nice and easy.
There you go.
Chipotle ketchup.
All right.
Get that other piece.
-Nice.
-Cut it.
The Brick's
meatloaf sandwich.
Was the name Brick just
because of the size of this?
Mm.
That's a real good move.
The meatloaf has got
really nice texture.
The rye bread really
plays in nicely.
Mm. That's crazy.
The chipotle ketchup
carries the torch for this,
but the wheatberry bread
really does give nice crunch,
a wholesomeness to it.
Good job, Ms. Chipotle Ketchup.
That's just how we do it.
Here's your meatloaf
and sweet potato fries.
I dig it.
It's a last-meal sandwich,
you know, moist,
spicy and crusty bread.
WOMAN: Their meatloaf is some
of the best I've ever had.
The chipotle ketchup,
I think, is the kicker.
I think so too.
It's really good.
Carolina.
We got a Carolina.
Food has always
been wonderful.
I love everything.
You come here to eat,
you're going to be happy.
-Turkey Florentine?
-And it's not just the food.
It's the atmosphere.
See your friends play some music
and have a meatloaf sandwich,
and it's a good night.
Excellent job. It's quaint.
It's got good energy.
You're here,
make the food yourself.
To me, what more
could you ask for?
It's the bomb.
It's the Brick.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
You know this is going Roadhouse
when you have
non-matching forks.
Awesome.
That is the entree fork,
and that is the entree fork.