Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri, and we're rolling
out looking for
America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Come on, look at that!
No knife and fork today.
You eat it
the way you like.
[ Laughs ]
'Cause we're literally grabbing
some gangster grub.
That's raindrops
in Flavortown, folks.
Like legit tacos in Atlanta.
You'll love this.
And prime-time burgers
in Salt Lake.
Oh, my gosh!
Plus, we're getting crazy
with the kolaches.
Three, two, go.
And feeling the need...
What in the world?!
...for speed.
You're an animal.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So "Triple D" is all about
finding the funky mom
and pop joints
all around the country.
Well, now I guess it's kind
of like all around the world.
So I'm here in Salt Lake City,
Utah,
where three buddies are living
the all-American dream.
You see, they're sitting
around saying,
"Hey, one day, man,
let's open up a brewery."
"Yeah, and right next to it,
we'll open up a burger joint."
Well, these three made
it happen.
This is Proper Burger Company.
I'm gonna start dropping
more burgers.
Food's fantastic.
I mean, they have such
a variety of burgers.
Vegan Bollywood, order up!
And the beer is amazing.
FIERI: I got a melting pot
of people here,
everybody likes
burgers and beer.
Which is why brothers Liam
and Rio Connelly and buddy
Andrew Tendick doubled down with
their side-by-side businesses.
You make beer.
You sell the beer over there
in the bar.
Then you also take the beer,
ad you bring it over here
to the burger company
and use it
in the recipes here.
Yep.
FIERI: And their burger boss
is Chef Jeff Springer...
Swinging two pork cities.
FIERI: ...who's definitely
not sticking
to the same old same old.
Double rarebit order up!
The rarebit has house-made
beer-cheese -- super unique.
Chef, what are we making.
Today, we're making
our rarebit sauce.
And what do you know
about rarebit sauce?
It's a beer-cheese sauce.
They believe it comes
from the Welsh.
He had me at hello
with that one.
We're gonna heat up our milk,
and then this is our amber ale.
Got it.
Then we're gonna bring this up
to simmer.
Simmer down now.
Now we're going
to make the roux.
Bacon fat, butter.
This is a bikini-weather sauce
if I've ever seen it.
Sweat some onion.
All-purpose flour.
The Worcestershire sauce.
Worcestershire sauce.
White wine vinegar.
Hurry up before I eat
all the cheese.
Salt.
Whole-grain mustard.
Thyme.
Now we're gonna add
our melted beer.
This is the European version
of nacho cheese.
I'm gonna transfer this
into a 22-quart.
Add our Irish cheddar
and the gorgonzola.
We're gonna put this burger
together now?
Yep.
Two patties down.
Two patties?
Never frozen, locally sourced,
grass-fed.
Just kind of warm up
the bacon.
That fry is legit.
The house-cut double fry.
Yes.
Oh.
Imagine that with some rarebit
on it, too.
I don't even have
to imagine it.
[ Laughs ]
That rarebit sauce is everything
I love in a cheese sauce.
It's got the tang.
You get the underlying notes
of the mustard.
Oh, that's good!
We've got a really good sear
on the burger now.
Look at that crust.
Gorgeous.
I'm gonna stack these two
on top,
and we're gonna add the bacon
right on top of this.
Okay.
Whole-grain mustard,
sliced tomatoes,
red onion, rarebit sauce
right over the top.
And that's all she wrote.
Delicious.
I just want to taste
the meat by itself.
It's seared super-hot
so you get
this really nice caramelization
on both sides.
And then it's still
tender and pink.
Mmm!
The rarebit sauce is money.
All day long, money.
I want a gallon
for the rarebit to go.
Dynamite job, Chef.
Got the rarebit burger.
Really hits the spot.
Everything you want in a burger.
All the flavors
go really well together.
If I could just drink the sauce,
I would.
But I can't,
so I drink the beer, too.
How did these guys
do with their beer?
Some of the best beer
in the state.
The styles that they do here
is something totally different.
They do a gose, that's a salted
beer, which is pretty fun.
Their experimentation
with the beer is also reflected
in their experimentation
in the burgers that they make.
Hipster burger, order up!
I mean, you don't get
a Pork City just anywhere.
Here we have the Pork City.
MAN: They've got house-made ham
and bacon on it,
and what's not to like?
What are we gonna do now?
The brine for the ham.
First,
we do some brown sugar.
Salt.
Curing salt.
Cumin, fennel seed,
juniper berries.
Nice.
And some cinnamon stick.
The water goes in.
How long is the brine
gonna simmer?
Five minutes.
Now the ice is to cool it down
so we don't poach the ham
when it goes in the brine.
Got it.
Okay.
This is a deboned shoulder.
Boning these yourself?
Yep.
Tie 'em myself as well,
so...
Well done on that.
Brown our ham 10 days and
smoke it for about four hours.
Pull it out and braze at 275
to 300 for about five hours.
Wow.
Mayo gone wild, eh?
Every bit that they had
in Salt Lake City.
We're gonna make
our beer aioli.
Chopped garlic,
roasted garlic.
Lemon juice.
Proper beer that we used
in the rarebit.
Salt and some black pepper.
Get it!
Right into the mayo.
Chopped parsley on top.
I'm standing back.
If that thing comes out,
it's gonna paint the room.
Oh, that's dynamite.
You get that beer, but you gotta
love the roasted garlic
and the fresh garlic,
without question.
Now we are going to take our ham
and slice it.
Four slices
on this one burger?
We'll do three slices
on the burger.
Oh, you did four so you and
I have something to snack on.
Yeah, yeah, right.
It don't get any better
than that.
Nice little hit of smoke,
tender.
Third-pound patty,
a little smoked ham, and bacon.
This is the beer aioli
that we made.
Buns toasted -- beautiful.
Bottom and top.
You're a good man.
The ham on top first,
bacon on top of that.
And some American cheese
on top.
All right.
Get this domed
and melted down.
Tomatoes.
Pickled jalapeños.
We also make these
in-house.
Let me see where your cape is,
Superman.
Finish it off
with some French fries.
And that is
the Pork City, USA.
That's raindrops
in Flavortown, folks.
♪♪
You got a bath towel?
[ Laughs ]
I love everything
about that burger.
It all starts with that
grass-fed beef, never frozen.
The double sear on the burger.
Treating both sides of the bun.
The crunch of the French fry,
little smokiness of the ham.
The bacon,
the beer aioli...
Great jalapeños,
by the way.
I mean, you're hitting
all the floors of flavor.
That's a burger with respect.
Nicely done.
Thank you, sir.
SERVER: Here's your
Pork City burger. Enjoy.
Pork City,
are you kidding me?
It's just perfect.
Fries right on it.
WOMAN: Very bacony.
Great sauce.
I couldn't help
but eat all mine.
The Veggie Mariachi.
Everyone feels welcomed here.
You want to keep coming back.
FIERI: You're living
the American dream.
There are so many people
watching this going,
"I want to have a brewery,
and I want to open
a burger joint.
All I want besides that is
an arcade and a bowling alley."
We've got almost
an arcade next door.
Yeah, Skee-Ball,
a few other things.
Okay.
No bowling alley, though.
Nice talking to you guys.
FIERI: Up next, we're staying
in Salt Lake...
Oh, you make this
look easy.
...for a Czech-Texan
specialty...
-We're Czexans.
-You've heard of the Czexans.
...packed with personality.
[ Laughs ] This is more fun.
I don't even know if we're
making food.
♪♪
No matter what culture you talk
about, everybody's got one.
It's something that's meat or
sweet and it's wrapped in dough.
Let's see, we could be talking
about an empanada,
a pupusa,
it could be a pork butt.
So when you have three siblings
from Houston
with a Czech family background,
they come out here
to Salt Lake City, Utah,
and they open up a joint,
it can only be called one thing,
and that is Hruska's Kolaches.
Can I have a Ranchero
and a Mexican omelet, please?
A kolache is a bun filled
with breakfast meat and eggs
and cheese and stuff.
It's a hug.
It's happy food.
You got blackberry
and cherry cream.
You have to eat these.
You won't be able to stop.
FIERI: That's what the Hruska
siblings were banking on
when they came
to college in Utah
and this their favorite Czech
dish they grew up with in Texas.
Hey, you know, we're Czech,
we're Texan.
There's no kolaches up here,
let's go ahead and--
Your Czexan.
We're Czexan.
-We're Czexan.
-You've heard of the Czexans.
So this is more of a breakfast
type item?
It is breakfast.
Can I get two sausage
and gravy.
Two sausage and gravy.
MAN: The sausage is just right
and coming from Texas,
they know how to make
a good homestyle gravy.
Okay, what are we making?
So we're making
our kolache dough.
Okay.
First, we're gonna start off
with some nice whole milk,
and then melted butter
and margarine.
Butter and margarine?
Mm-hmm.
This is a variation of our
great-grandmother's recipe.
Okay.
All-purpose flour, sugar.
The high-gluten flour.
Salt, egg yolk.
What were those again?
Yeah, I knew you'd say it.
Excuse me.
There are egg yolks.
I know, I pronounce the "L,"
and I didn't know it was bad
until I came to college.
[ Snorts ]
And a snort.
I'm sorry.
An egg yolk and a snort.
Oh, gosh,
it's gonna be on TV.
We have yeast.
And how long
we gonna mix this?
Maybe just a few minutes.
It's a melt-in-your-mouth
dough.
So this makes all the kolaches
the same size.
How many kolaches do you
make in a day?
Maybe, like, on average,
a thousand.
That's a locha-kolache.
It is.
Wow.
Oh, you make this
look easy.
In the cooking over for,
like, 30 minutes.
Let's hit it.
So we are making the sausage for
our sausage and gravy kolache.
Okay.
Onion powder.
Granulated garlic.
Salt, fresh-ground pepper.
And then...
Fresh-cut sage.
Yeah.
And this is just pork and beef.
Little water in there.
Start cooking that down,
and then we're gonna make
the gravy right in with
the sausage right now as we go?
Yeah.
Salt, pepper, flour,
a little bit of milk.
Yep.
Let that cool.
And then stuff it.
Mm-hmm.
So you just take your dough
and fill it
with the sausage
and gravy filling.
Whoa, that's a good portion.
Pinch it.
Set it down on the pinch.
How long are they gonna bake?
Roughly 20 minutes.
Heavy.
It's pretty heavy.
And is there a way
that you eat them?
Everything's with hands.
Just wait for it to not
burn your face off.
A little hot.
[ Laughing ]
Yeah, I like...
It's delicious.
Thank you.
The dough is yeasty.
Yeah.
That's what I really
like about it.
Yeah.
It's light, it's airy,
but it's hearty enough
that it really does
give you enough texture.
The gravy with the sausage,
it's tender, it's moist.
There's a lot of depth
of flavor.
That's a full meal.
Thank you.
And especially on the run.
It's fantastic.
All right, we got
sausage and gravy.
Rich, delicious gravy --
I love it.
You get all kinds
of flavor profiles,
and it's all
in one tight little package.
And the dough
is so good.
-Going in the oven for 10.
-Perfect.
WOMAN: It's a really fun place
to come and eat.
The owners are always so happy
and friendly
when you come in here.
Whoo!
Okay.
Was that a little sing?
It was.
Was that a little
singing there?
I just make
sound effects.
You have --
evidentially.
I'm putting together
a soundtrack.
Aah.
[ Whooshing ]
Plop. Mmm!
Ooh.
Psst.
I can't even do that.
[ Laughs ]
This is more fun.
I don't even know
if we're making food.
[ Laughing ] Okay.
FIERI: But, seriously,
this place is getting after it,
putting out plenty of fillings
to choose from.
So we're gonna make
a sweet one next.
Yeah.
All right,
we got raspberry cream.
FIERI: Getting a taste, well,
that's another story.
[ Laughs ]
These are great, but the
comedy show is hysterical.
What is the sound effect right
now when we're doing the...
I go... [ Whooshing ]
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
So welcome back.
"Triple D" in Salt
Lake City, Utah,
hanging out at Hruska's...
Kolaches.
Hruska's Kolaches.
Mm-hmm.
You know what, I love the fact
that you made the name so easy
for people to say.
Yeah, strange name,
delicious food.
Kolaches are Czech,
and it's kind of nice to get
a little bit of Eastern Europe
in Salt Lake City.
What can we do for ya?
Kolache is a buttery,
yeast break,
and then you can stuff
or top them.
Traditionally,
kolaches are sweet.
A raspberry cream cheese,
please.
Okay.
Raspberry and cream
is kind of always good.
It's just got a nice balance
of kind of sweet and tart.
FIERI: All right, so now
what are we making?
Our raspberry filling.
Okay.
So we're gonna start off wish
some lemon concentrate,
apple concentrate,
crushed raspberries.
Sugar.
Once this comes to a boil,
then we add Clear Jel
of corn starch isolate.
Let this tighten up,
let it cool.
Yeah, we put it
in a piping bag.
All right,
what are we making?
Our cream cheese filling.
We start off with cream
cheese and sugar.
We're just gonna
cream it out.
And then we're gonna add
our egg yolks.
I love when the yolks
make it in.
Once we got that all
creamed together,
we're gonna
put in cottage cheese.
Mmm.
Which is a really
traditional Czech filling.
Same dough.
We're gonna
stomp 'em all out.
You want me to time you?
Sure.
How long do you think
it takes you?
Less than a minute.
I'm gonna stomp, I'm gonna fill,
I'm gonna fill.
You're gonna do all that
in a minute?
Yeah.
Three, two, go.
What in the--
13 seconds.
I'm going too fast,
I'm making these ugly.
27 seconds.
34 seconds.
What in the world?!
Those are so ugly,
though.
You're an animal!
Now how long will this
take to bake?
Eight minutes.
I actually like these ones
right out of the oven,
just a couple minutes
cooled
so the cream cheese sets
just a little bit.
'Cause right now,
that's a--
I like to dip,
but you eat it
the way you like.
[ Chuckles ]
It looks good.
I want to eat one.
You can take a full bite if you
want, you don't have to dip it.
Thank you.
Okay.
Make me nervous.
[ Laughs ]
Here it goes.
I knew she couldn't resist.
Come down.
These are great, but the comedy
show is hysterical.
It's delicious.
I mean, you're making high-end
quality pastry,
fresh-made
with a lot of creativity
and a lot of variety,
and I'm not a sweets guy.
I'm not a pastry guy.
But this right here
is a mature pastry
that has great texture of
the crust, very nice and light.
But a good contrast between
the sour and the sweet.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
We got raspberry cream.
The frosting, filling stuffed
in the middle is really good.
MAN:
The way the raspberries come
together with the cream cheese
is just a heavenly union,
really.
Can I get a sausage gravy
and a maple pecan?
I love this place.
It's not your typical
breakfast sandwich.
Really tasty, a lot of variety,
and interesting.
On top of it all, with you
and your two brothers
making this happen,
offering something that people
probably haven't had before,
offering something that comes
from your family history,
and I think you're having a
great time while you do it.
Yeah, I do.
I love it.
Real deal.
What's our good-bye music?
♪ Da-da, da-da, da, da ♪
[ Laughing ] I don't know.
FIERI:
Coming up, an Atlanta chef
throwing fine-dining chops...
My mouth is watering,
by the way.
...into real deal tacos.
I don't know, Chef,
what I like better --
the flavor the tacos
or the passion
that you have
for what you do.
♪♪
You gotta love
"Triple D" joints.
These mom and pop places
with these funky backstories.
So check this one out.
I'm here in Atlanta to check out
a place
where the chef
is raised in Mexico,
gets his college degree
and decides,
"Hey, I'll just move to Paris
and go to Le Cordon Bleu
and do a stage at some
Michelin-starred restaurants."
And when he gets finished
with that, he says,
"You know what?
Now it's time to move
to the States to Atlanta
and open up a taco shop."
This is Rreal Tacos.
Those tacos are there
in the window.
The best tacos in town.
They are so authentic.
SERVER: Carnitas tacos.
A lot of street taco flavors
that you would see
in Mexico you find here.
FIERI: Flavors that owner
Adrian Villarreal
missed after years
of French fine dining.
Those are on the double.
FIERI:
So he refocused his culinary
chops on the cuisine
of his Mexican homeland.
Everybody loves tacos.
When you go to Mexico,
tacos are very simple.
The ingredients are usually
very fresh and made correctly.
Uh-huh.
And that's it.
Yeah.
And that's his mission.
Chicken Veracruzana going down.
I've tried every taco
on the menu.
The Chicken Veracruz taco
is one of my favorites.
A real juicy chicken taco.
The taste is amazing.
What are we making?
We're gonna do
our Veracruzana sauce.
Veracruzana.
So start with your oil.
Peppers and onions, garlic,
salt, chili flakes,
and you let it sweat down.
Okay.
We add your tomatoes,
some olives, some capers.
Cilantro,
and your epazote.
So epazote is something
we traditionally don't find
in the United States.
Not that much.
And you only
find it in more
of the authentic style
Mexican restaurants.
Yes, that's for sure.
How are we gonna cook
the chicken?
Add some onion, garlic, salt,
and bay leaf.
Very simple.
Simmer for about an hour
and a half.
We shred it,
and we keep the skin.
Don't want to lose
the flavor of the skin.
Yes.
Add a little bit of the stock
to get it simmering.
We got our Veracruzana
ready to go,
and you just ladle it
into it.
My mouth is watering,
by the way.
So then the fried avocado.
You say fried avocado,
and I love it.
The slurry is just corn starch,
a little bit of water,
a little bit of salt.
What are we gonna
dredge it in?
Masa harina
and some spices.
is the same thing
that you make tortillas
and tamales out of.
Fry them in canola oil.
Yes.
Let's fill those tacos.
We're doing the flour tortillas
for this guy.
Boy, that's not any little
Mexican street taco portion.
Definitely not. You like onion
and cilantro, right?
Come on.
Okay.
The crispy avocado.
Do I get three or four?
You get four.
Don't cheat me over there.
People get three,
you get four.
We got our
cilantro dressing.
♪♪
Oh.
That right there in the world
of fried avocado
is in its own category.
Thank you.
The cross between the corn
starch and the masa harina,
this has, like,
cracker crunch to it.
Dynamite.
All right.
Mmm.
That is a meaningful,
well-executed,
delicious chicken taco.
Thank you for noticing.
There's tender chicken,
vegetables still with some bite.
The Veracruz sauce,
delicious.
And a nice little bit of acid
from the onions
and the herbaceousness
from the cilantro.
Yep.
It's all real-deal
Mexican flavors
with ridiculous
gringo portions.
[ Laughing ] Yes, sir.
Oh, just one more bite.
Dos tacos Veracruzana
in the window.
Very hearty meal.
It's very juicy.
How about the fried avocados?
What do you think?
-They're amazing.
-Very good.
Dos carnitas up there!
These's a lot of competition
for tacos here in the city,
and I really believe
this place stands out.
Why R-real?
Rreal because of my last name,
Villarreal.
And to people go "R-Real Tacos"?
R-Real?
R-Real Tacos are the most common
or just Real Tacos.
Nobody goes "Rreal Tacos."
That does not happen.
I'm talking on the phone,
I'm not gonna say "Rreal Tacos."
No?
No.
Why not?
Nobody's gonna understand
where I'm coming from.
[ Rolls tongue ] "Rreal Tacos.
Rreal Tacos."
I think Rreal Taco
is really special.
My favorite is the Pork Trompo.
Trompo Taco in the window.
It's crispy in all
the right ways.
MAN: They cook it
fresh every day.
They cut it right off the stack.
Why do you call it
Trompo taco?
That's how we call it
where I'm from.
And most people know
it as pastor.
So start it off.
So guajillo peppers,
clove.
Brown sugar?
Mm-hmm.
Some salt, vinegar, garlic,
and annatto seeds.
Gives that nice red hue.
Some cumin, oregano,
and epazote.
Okay.
A little bit of water,
a little bit of--
A little tequila.
Yes, tequila.
That came before.
Yes.
Let it rip.
"Let it rip."
Did you ever play the football
game when you were a kid?
You had a little
football game,
those little guys
vibrated around.
Let's see which one wins.
Which one are you gonna take?
Oregano.
I'll take the epazote.
Here we go.
Come on!
Look at that!
Epazote!
[ Laughs ]
I did not win?
Easily entertained.
Hi, I'm four.
So I'm gonna take this.
A little extra salt.
We're using pork butt?
Yes.
Give it a couple of hours.
Stack these up
and build a trompo.
You're gonna love this.
From here, straight
into the rotisserie.
Look at that.
That's the goods right there.
You definitely taste
the guajillo.
Yes.
I like that crispiness when it's
so close to the flame.
Gives it a little reminiscence
of a little chicharron.
Yeah.
All right,
let's make a taco.
These are house-made
tortillas.
We got the pork trompo,
cilantro.
Okay.
You got your limes.
♪♪
I don't know,
Chef, what I like better,
the flavor of the tacos
or the passion
that you have
for what you do.
Thank you.
You treat this with the same
level of expertise
that most people would expect
a Michelin restaurant to have.
If you want authentic
flavors...
done right,
these are your tacos.
Here we have
your Trompo Tacos.
It's so fresh
and it's so flavorful.
Stuffed with a lot of meat,
a lot of spices.
-Out of bounds.
-That's my line.
Cut this guy out.
[ Speaking Spanish ] Go!
When I come in here, I really
feel like I'm in Mexico.
When you called it Rreal Tacos,
you backed it up.
Thank you.
Nicely done.
This guy.
So what that another
righteous road trip, or what?
But don't you worry --
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
Okay, watch this.
Okay.
Yeah, we still got ghosts --
awesome.
It's a ghost that can't see
very well.