Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Get ready for
all‐American favorites...
You got a lot
goin' on here.
...and worldwide flavor.
No one leaves here
hungry.
No one leaves here.
I saw people camped out
over at Booth 4.
Like the joint
in Santa Rosa, California...
I'm gonna drowned
in my own drool,
is what I'm gonna do.
...bangin' out a burrito
[chuckle] that got my attention.
I try it and I
lose. my. mind.
And, in Little Rock...
Holy pterodactyl.
...we're grabbin'
a big bite of burgers...
Exactly what anaconda is
gonna come and eat that?
...and a taste [chuckle]
of Little Italy.
This is dangerous.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins &amp; Dives."
♪♪♪♪
So, "Triple D."
what's it about?
It's about findin' these
mom‐and‐pop joints
off the beaten path.
But it's grown
into more than that.
I say, if it's funky,
I'll find it.
We're looking for places
that have family,
that have tradition,
and families that are keepin'
that tradition alive.
Right here,
in Little Rock, Arkansas,
this is Bruno's Little Italy.
♪♪♪♪
Spaghetti carbonara,
Table 12.
Good Italian food.
I've got a pizza
mista for ya.
This place has been
the Italian place in Arkansas
since after World War II.
FIERI:
All starting in 1948,
when GI Vincent Bruno,
aka Jimmy,
opened this joint after he was
stationed nearby during the war.
The ambiance and the warmth
that Jimmy Bruno created
emanates through his two sons
Vince and Gio.
FIERI:
And the brothers Bruno have been
the heart and soul of this place
since they took over
the reigns in 1985.
To see what you guys are doin'
and that you're carrying
that same energy
that your pops carried,
that's the whole reason I came.
We've got people that ate
at Bruno's
before we were born,
‐Oh, yeah.
that come in and they want it
to taste like it did back then.
That's exactly
what it is.
Cannelloni, Table 14.
The menu has changed
very little.
Everything here is homemade.
Toasted ravioli,
Table 34.
I'm havin' the toasted
ravioli today.
It's amazingly
delicious.
Now this is the filling
for the ravioli?
‐For the toasted ravioli.
‐So, ricotta cheese.
Eggs, freshly grated
Romano cheese.
Romano? Nice tang.
‐Parsley.
‐Okay.
Salt and pepper.
Butter.
And this is the recipe
your pops was using?
‐Absolutely.
‐This has not changed?
‐Not at all.
‐Not even if somebody walked in
and said, "You know what?
The new thing
that everybody's
puttin' into it is..."?
‐Bye.
‐Bye, as in
‐Buh‐bye.
You use
good ingredients,
cook it the right way,
keep it simple.
That's what Dad's key was.
‐[Banging]
‐That's what he said.
How you like it?
[laughing] Yeah.
‐Mmm.
It's simple, but good.
So run me through
makin' the pasta.
It is oil, eggs, and the milk,
salt, flour.
‐All‐purpose flour?
‐Actually, I use
a hard winter wheat,
high‐gluten.
So, we're gonna get
all that chew
and all that texture
out of that, okay.
‐Quite right.
‐Have you ever thought
of just buying
pre‐made pasta?
Someone suggested that
one time.
They're not around.
‐They're not around anymore?
Okay.
‐[Laughing]
All right.
[ Outro plays ]
[ Scraping ]
[ Lullaby plays ]
‐Zzz.
‐[laughing] Oh.
Wow.
You're killin' me.
‐I'm sorry. Are we back?
It puts you to sleep, man.
I apologize. Whew!
Your nickname's
speed demon, isn't it?
More than you
would ever know.
I'm gonna go do a brake
job on my Camaro.
‐[Laughing]
‐I'll be back.
You keep nailin' 'em,
Speedy.
See ya on Thursday.
‐Ooh!
Gonna make me cry.
Little sprinkle of water.
‐That's it?
‐That's the key.
‐There you go. That's the key.
[whispering] You're
using the wrong end.
This one? No, no.
That's how I do it.
That's where that comes in.
‐Gotcha.
I love this.
Now we're just gonna
zip 'em off.
Two and a half
orders, folks.
Done, record time.
‐[Laughing]
Now these
will get frozen,
‐Yes.
‐then dredged in a...
‐Egg wash, cracker meal.
‐Okay.
Fry 'em up.
[ Sizzling ]
I like that we call 'em
toasted, but we fried 'em.
Correct.
Now who are you
tryin' to tease
with that thimble
of sauce?
You know all that sauce
is sayin' to me is,
"Order some more, please."
‐Exactly.
And then we've got
freshly grated Romano cheese.
So Romano is what you
like to use here,
more than Parmesan?
‐I do, and Dad did, too.
A little parsley.
And this is one of the
staples of Bruno's.
Probably one of the
biggest‐selling things
in all the years
we've been open.
♪♪♪♪
The Romano is just
a awesome choice.
The saltiness of it.
That's spot‐on.
I can't say any time
that I've had toasted
ravioli like this.
It's nice and it's light.
It's simple,
but flavorful.
You're specific
about the cheese.
It all goes together
in balance.
♪♪♪♪
This is dangerous.
And what a great meat sauce.
The only thing
I want you to change...
[tapping spoon]
is that.
You've done it, man.
Excellent job.
‐Toasted ravioli
for each of you.
‐Thank you.
It is real good and tasty.
I eat 'em all the time
when I come here.
It's crispy on the outside
and luscious on the inside.
I've had this since I was
a little kid.
I've been to Bruno's
for just under 70 years.
Jimmy Bruno would sing to us,
which I thought was
pretty incredible.
His father was
the first customer;
and he was the first customer
at this location.
I see the dish on the menu
that was named after my mother
when she was pregnant with me.
What, does everybody got
their name on a wall
and a picture and a thing?
It's just like you're comin'
into a family gathering.
We're at Bruno's.
The two brothers
are knockin' it
out of the park,
keepin' the recipes
exactly the same.
When we come back,
what are we gonna make?
We're gonna make
my dad's lasagna.
‐Oldschool.
‐Never changed it?
‐Never changed it.
‐Real‐deal.
We'll see you in a bit.
All right,
but we need more sauce.
I'm gonna get you
more sauce right now.
♪♪♪♪
Welcome back.
Hangin' out at Bruno's
in Little Rock, Arkansas,
and I gotta tell ya,
my buddy Vincenzo here ‐‐
Vincenzo, what's
your full name again?
Vincenzo Gennaro
Nicola Bruno.
So he and his brother
have taken over this joint
that their dad
started back in the '40s,
an oldschool
Italian restaurant.
Chicken Vincenzo,
Table 14.
You don't come here
unless you're very hungry.
They still throw the pizzas
and they have pasta dishes.
Lasagna, Table 42.
The lasagna
is so wonderful.
It's just
incredibly seasoned.
The sauce is always on point.
FIERI:
What are we doin' next?
We're fixin; to make
meat sauce.
Okay, fixin' to make it.
We got some oil,
fresh‐chopped garlic.
‐Holy moly!
‐[laughing] I know.
Coarse‐ground beef.
‐No pork goes into this?
‐No pork.
'Cause old Jimmy Bruno...
Doesn't want pork
in his meat sauce.
...doesn't want pork.
'Cause he would've put it
in there, if he
wanted it that way.
That's right.
Ground pear tomatoes.
‐Tomato paste.
‐Salt and pepper.
‐There you go.
Basil. Parsley.
How long is this
gonna cook down?
I usually cook it
for six hours.
This is our homemade
Italian sausage.
‐Okay.
‐Homemade meatballs.
Got it. So what's
in the Italian sausage?
Pepper, crushed red pepper;
fennel seed; salt.
‐Okay.
‐Pork and beef in this one.
Case the sausage?
Yes.
Dynamite. Look at all
that fennel, dude.
You did ‐‐ No, it's great,
'cause I love fennel.
We love fennel. Yeah.
I do, too.
Meatballs.
What's in these?
Salt, pepper, garlic,
Romano cheese,
breadcrumbs, eggs,
pine nuts.
‐Really?!
I cook 'em
in a cast‐iron skillet.
Every one of them.
Dynamite. Why am I trying
these without pasta?
Those are two
of the ingredients
that are ground
into the lasagna mix.
We've got the...
‐Sausage and meatballs.
‐Okay. Got it.
Soppressata, prosciutto ham.
‐What's the cheese?
‐Mozzarella.
Then we've got ricotta,
butter, parsley,
salt and pepper, eggs...
‐And let me guess.
‐Romano.
Is there any Parmesan
cheese in the house?
‐No.
‐How many layers in the lasagna?
Two. They're
pretty thick, though.
No one leaves here hungry.
‐No one leaves here.
I saw people camped out
over at Booth 4.
[laughing] Oh, yeah.
Now, we make the lasagna.
Now we make it.
The pasta sheets have been
blanched in salt water?
Yes.
I'm just gonna oil this up.
I'm gonna start here.
A lotta pasta.
[whistles]
‐The mixture.
‐You're a dangerous man.
Now, we're gonna put
meat sauce on it.
More pasta. [laughs]
♪♪♪♪
And this is gonna
bake at what,
350,
for how many hours?
For 3.5 hours.
‐It's a monster.
‐[Laughs]
I like corner piece.
All right.
Meat sauce on top.
Little bit of parsley.
How about a little basil
for garnish?
You're ready to rock.
‐There's no way
I can eat even half of this.
It's delicious.
For such a big, monster lasagna,
it's very light.
You get tender pasta,
then you get this nice,
creamy balance from the ricotta.
‐Right.
Then, all of a sudden,
you get a little bit
of the springiness
of the mozzarella cheese.
Then, you get a little texture
of the sausage
and the Soppressata,
then you get a little salty bit
comin' through
from the prosciutto.
‐Right.
Then, you just get the really
nice, tender meatball.
It far exceeds
my expectations.
Thank you.
Lasagna, Table 33.
This is the best lasagna
I've ever put in my mouth.
Can you eat
that whole lasagna?
I could eat another one.
No problem.
‐Got our lasagnas.
‐Oh, yay! That's mine.
When I want Italian food,
this is where I come.
Bruno's gonna outlast 'em all.
FIERI:
It's delicious
and it's oldschool.
I don't know how much of this
is a business and a job
and how much of this
is just throwing your own
personal party every day.
‐I love what I do.
‐And it shows.
Every bit.
‐You're just like
your pops, man.
That's real‐deal.
Good job.
Thank you, brother.
Thank you.
Comin' up...
in Santa Rosa, California...
Are we related?
...a spot stayin' local
while goin' global...
I wanna call it
high‐end fast food.
...servin' a dish I just had
to come back for.
Do I want a bite?
Do I want 20 bites?
Which way?
[ Laughing ]
Let's dance.
[laughing] Let's dance.
[ Laughing ]
[ Beep ]
♪♪♪♪
So, there are a lotta ways
that a restaurant
ends up on "Triple D."
Most of the time, it's the
recommendation of the viewers,
but then, we got families
and friends and cousins
and you name it.
But every once in a while,
I come through
with the location.
So here we are
in Santa Rosa, California,
and this is a place
where a buddy of mine
brought me a burrito.
The burrito was so fantastic,
I said, "Listen,
if the rest of the menu
can back up this burrito,
they're makin' it on the show."
And here we are.
This is Zoftig Eatery.
♪♪♪♪
Poke bowl's ready.
The food here is delicious:
fresh, flavorful.
Pick up Italian pork.
It's not just like
one specific type of cuisine.
It's all really different.
FIERI:
That variety comes from the one
and only chef and owner,
Matt Spector, who's tappin'
into his fine‐dining background
to spice up
this breakfast/lunch menu.
How do you describe
what Zoftig's about?
Everything is made here,
it's good ingredients,
usin' local produce.
We get it quickly.
I wanna call it
high‐end fast food.
There you go.
Now they're sourcing local,
but their menu is peppered
with global flavor.
Korean burrito.
Burrito's great.
It has a tanginess to it,
it has a little spiciness
with the kimchi.
The meat is always warm,
the vegetables are cold.
It's like the
perfect contrast.
It tastes amazing.
Let's make it happen.
We're gonna make
our Korean barbecue sauce
for the Korean burrito.
It's just oil,
ginger, garlic,
hot peppers,
chili paste here.
Let that break down
a little bit.
Rice‐wine vinegar, sugar,
soy sauce goes in.
Just a little bit of water.
We're gonna let this simmer
down a little bit.
Now, we're gonna make
the marinade for the beef.
All right,
get it goin'.
Sugar, soy, rice vinegar,
some garlic,
jalapeño, ginger.
I leave the skins on.
I like the spice.
Fish sauce.
‐Give it a little kick
of some fish sauce
and it will up your game.
The marinade goes
in the ground beef.
[ Sizzling ]
We get our beef in there.
And we're gonna add the rice
to it and absorb it.
We use short‐grain,
organic brown rice.
We have our tortilla
warmed up.
Our pickled daikon and carrot,
our house‐pickled red onions,
kimchi, fresh mint,
and cilantro.
Crushes it.
Avocado, green onion.
Our barbecue sauce,
to finish everything up.
Boom.
Little drizz of that.
"A little drizz."
Wrap 'er up.
Now, you can smell it,
right?
I ‐‐ Can I smell it?
I'm gonna drowned
in my own drool,
is what I'm gonna do.
Looks pretty good.
Could I have a bite?
‐Oh, go, yeah.
‐[Laughs]
♪♪♪♪
That is good.
Unh‐unh. Not good.
It's fantastic.
It's that combo of the
cilantro and the mint
that add that little kick
right at the end of it.
Yeah.
You got great acid,
got good heat,
got good pickle.
You know what it is, though,
the common thread?
Was the barbecue sauce.
‐Yeah.
It plays all the way through.
You gonna finish yours,
or can I take this to go?
‐No. Yeah.
‐Good. I'll just
put these in the car.
[ Laughing ]
‐Here's your Korean burrito.
‐Thank you.
The Korean burrito has
a great variety of flavors.
It's got a variety
of textures.
Want a bite?
Do I want a bite?
Do I want 20 bites?
‐Good.
‐'Cause, you see,
this is the bad boy
that sold me on this joint,
in the first place.
We're here in Santa Rosa
and we're shooting
"Guy's Grocery Games."
One of my best friends
brings me a burrito.
I try it and I
lose. my. mind.
Which led me to come down here
to see what else
they've got up their sleeve.
Roasted‐chicken
sandwich.
‐Favorite thing on the menu?
‐Maccabi bowl.
Maccabi bowl is ready.
Maccabi bowl's like
a treasure chest,
with little surprises
all the way through.
Falafel and baba ganoush
and...?
A little hummus
and a little beet dip,
which we're about to make.
‐Can't beet it. [beat]
‐Right.
Our roasted beets, yogurt,
toasted walnuts,
Madras curry, and we have
some lime here, too,
'cause it could use some acid.
‐Okay.
‐Pulse that a few times.
The beet salad is done.
Now, we're gonna make
farro tabbouleh.
Listen,
I'm a farro junkie.
I like the toothiness of it.
It seems like you can't
overcook it.
‐Are we related?
‐Maybe.
Farro in the bowl,
red onion,
cucumber, parsley,
salt, pepper.
We always toast our black pepper
before we grind it.
Simple details
make all the difference.
‐Yeah.
‐Little olive oil.
Red‐wine vinegar.
Let that marinate
for a while.
You went to all
this extra effort
to make this one salad
that is only 1/5
of the components
that go together
for the maccabi salad.
Yeah.
It's what we do.
‐You got elves in the back?
‐[Laughing]
All right, so the falafel
starts with the marinade
for the chickpeas.
‐Got it.
In here, we have cilantro,
mint, parsley,
a little green onion,
jalapeños in,
salt, pepper, lemon juice.
Get everything goin'.
So our chickpeas,
we have our marinade,
a little bit of flour,
garlic powder, toasted cumin.
The beans go in
to be pureed.
I'm on the pit crew.
You see that?
I'm just jumpin' right in.
What size scoop?
What is this, 1.5?
I think, officially,
that's called
golf‐ball size.
‐The is golf‐ball size, yeah.
Let's drop 'em.
All right, put it
together, brother.
Some greens down, beet dip,
baba ganoush, our hummus,
mixed olives, tomato,
farro tabbouleh,
our extra virgin olive oil,
red‐wine vinegar again,
falafels.
This is just whole‐wheat
tortillas fried up here.
Do you want me
to go get the pliers
and the monkey wrench?
‐What's that for?
Well, I figured
we'd use it
to go take the kitchen sink
and put it in here
'cause that's
the only thing
that we don't have
in here. Huh?
♪♪♪♪
Hummus is great.
Falafel:
I love the little heat
that you put inside of that.
Get a little
of that beet salad.
The tabbouleh kicker,
that texture,
because you're starting
to get a lotta soft
‐Right.
‐and the acid.
You give more energy, time,
and effort in the little salad
than a lot of people put
in a whole lunch.
Right.
‐You're the real deal, man.
‐Yeah, for sure.
SERVER:
Maccabi bowl.
I love this bowl.
The flavors complement
each other so well.
The falafel's crispy
and crunchy,
but soft on the inside.
It has great flavor.
Veggie wrap ready.
Doesn't matter what you
choose off the menu.
It's all delicious.
‐Chef Matt,
what a pleasure, bud.
‐Thank you.
What a pleasure.
Watch out for this guy.
Zoftig for everybody.
Up next...
in Little Rock,
north, across the river...
Arkansas BBQ [mumbling]
bologna burger.
...a joint full of bologna...
It's called
the diet burger,
in case anybody asks.
...and some funky chicken.
Great flavor, great taste,
great sandwich.
♪♪♪♪
So I'm here
in North Little Rock, Arkansas.
Man, that's a mouthful.
Not to be confused
with Little Rock, Arkansas.
No, the Arkansas River
separates the two of them
and, if you're from
North Little Rock, Arkansas,
you want it to be
recognized that way.
Anyhow, let's get to the point.
There's two buddies
in high school.
They decide to open up
a joint together
and they like to call it
the NLR Gourmet Bar.
This is North Bar.
♪♪♪♪
Last Samurai burger.
The best burgers
in the state.
Green thumb
pesto burger.
The food's unique.
You can't find
anything like this
anywhere else.
FIERI:
And it all came about
after Chef Eric Greer
became Little Rock's
prodigal son.
Lived outta town
for a long time.
I came back to Arkansas
to visit
and my dad kinda
begged me to stay here
and so, I didn't go back.
You were done
missin' the kid?
Yeah, and the grandkids.
So Eric
paired up with his pops
and high school buddy
Kyle Dismang
to fire up all kinds
of not‐your‐everyday burgers.
Arkansas
bologna burger.
The Arkansas BBQ
bologna burger is fabulous.
It's different than anything
that I've ever had before.
‐What're we making, Chef?
‐We're gonna make
the Arkansas BBQ
bologna burger.
How do you
say that fast?
Arkansas BBQ [mumbling]
bologna burger.
Well, I've said it
a million times, so...
‐Say it again.
‐Arkansas BBQ bologna burger.
Say it
five times fast.
We're gonna make
the barbecue sauce.
Start off with the sugar,
put the cornstarch in,
put the ketchup in,
red‐wine vinegar.
Right there,
we could've said
we were makin'
sweet‐and‐sour sauce.
Pineapple juice,
and just a little salt
and pepper to taste.
Okay.
Put the lid on it
and we're gonna let it simmer.
What really kinda makes it dark
and rich and flavorful is
that it cooks
for about an hour and a half,
really, really slow and low.
‐Really reduces.
And that's all goin'
for this
BBQ bacon
bologna burger?
‐That's it.
‐I said it.
‐This is how
we patty 'em out.
We use plates, smash it down.
That's how we do it?
‐8 ounces.
‐Okay.
Place that baby right there
on the grill.
We're gonna slice
the bologna up.
Hang on a second.
Who gnawed off
the end of it?
What'd you cut it with
last time, a camping ax?
[ Laughing ]
Got a good slab of bologna.
‐I mean, look at that.
‐It's gonna be about 8 ounces.
It's called
the diet burger,
in case anybody asks.
‐Grab our brioche bun,
provolone cheese, pork rinds.
You making them
chicharrones?
‐Making 'em.
‐You're fryin' 'em up, huh?
‐We did it.
‐I'm tellin' you what.
‐I think everybody
likes those.
Put plenty of barbecue sauce.
I don't ever put
too less of sauce.
I like a lotta sauce.
‐"Too less o' sauce."
‐Then we're gonna put the patty
and your bologna,
put a burger setup on there,
top bun, our garnish,
and that's it.
Exactly what anaconda is
gonna come and eat that?
We have an outrageous
amount of people
who come here
and eat that burger.
I actually had one
before you came in here.
‐No, he didn't.
‐Yeah.
Jeez, dude.
That's a big‐boy
burger, man.
I don't know where
to attack it from,
the knee or the ankle.
‐[Laughing]
♪♪♪♪
Well, I like the tang on that
barbecue sauce, for sure.
You know those ponchos you wear
when you go to a football game?
That's what you need
to eat this thing.
There's not many places you can
get away with eating bologna,
but when you come
down to Arkansas,
you can find a lotta places
that are servin' it.
You put a little texture to it,
you let it dry out a bit,
so it's not so mushy,
you put that with a big burger,
some tangy barbecue sauce,
and a bun
that'll hold together,
you got yourself a party.
‐There we go.
‐We have bologna at home
all the time, but it's
never this thick‐cut.
It's never fried like this.
Bro, I mean,
it's as big as your head.
And, beyond the burger,
turns out these guys have become
North Little Rock trailblazers.
I feel like North Bar's
a bit of a beacon over here,
where most restaurants
are across the river.
I grew up right
in this neighborhood
and we never
had restaurants here,
so, to have a restaurant
like this is just fantastic.
There's everything
I want here.
Sweet‐and‐sour
chicken sandwich.
Talk to me about this
sweet‐and‐sour chicken sandwich.
It's a little messy,
but it's totally worth it.
Every time you take a bite,
you'll want it to never end.
‐All right, Chef.
‐We're gonna make a sauce
for the sweet‐and‐sour
chicken sandwich.
Okay.
Start with water.
Red‐wine vinegar.
Sweet‐and‐sour sauce
with hot sauce?
With ‐‐ Yes.
Must be a North Little Rock
kinda deal.
‐It is.
‐A buncha garlic.
‐Sugar, next.
‐And a little salt.
A little salt.
This cooks for about an hour.
It'll thicken up
and get sticky.
Next step?
We get our chicken in, fresh.
Holy pterodactyl.
Cut 'em in half,
dredge it in the buttermilk,
directly in the flour,
put it in the fryer.
Once it's done, we're gonna
build the burger up.
Burger
or chicken sandwich?
I call everything in here
a burger.
I'm gonna go have one
of those 12‐ounce,
‐Chicken.
‐cold burgers in a glass.
[ Laughter ]
They'll ‐‐ I mean, yeah.
We're gonna grab this chicken.
It's going straight
into the sweet‐and‐sour sauce.
‐Uh‐huh.
We're gonna put a piece
of provolone on next,
our romaine, sliced tomato,
top it off.
That's a chicken burger,
right there.
♪♪♪♪
Well, I'll tell you
what, buddy.
Bottle that sauce,
I would buy it, for sure.
Right amount of tang.
It is sweet and sour,
but it's sweet, sour, and heat.
Just a good, nice little
back spice to it.
It's what you love
in a hot wing.
It's what you
love in sweet‐and‐sour.
It's on a great bun.
Great flavor, great taste,
great sandwich.
[ Sizzling ]
The chicken is cooked
so gorgeously.
The sweet‐and‐sour is punchy,
but not overpowering.
Sweet‐and‐sour chicken,
going down.
MAN:
Everything keeps you
coming back.
Good craft beer,
good food.
‐And nice people.
‐Absolutely.
All right, guys,
here we go.
You got a lot goin' on here
and you got a good thing.
You're lucky to have your dad
workin' side‐by‐side,
and your buddy, as well.
Nice job, man.
‐All right.
[ Outro plays ]
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll be lookin' for more joints
all over this country!
I'll see ya next week on
"Diners, Drive‐Ins &amp; Dives."
So what did you do
before you started this?
I was in the tire business
for 24 years.
So, when you're in the tire
business and you quit,
do you re‐tire?
‐No.
‐Sorry.
Sorry. It was there.
I had to take the shot.
[ Laughter ]