Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Uh‐huh!
...it's a round‐the‐world
journey...
‐Come on, baby! Let's go!
‐I'm coming.
...all over the nation.
This is like
a magic show.
We got lights‐out Lebanese
in Salt Lake...
That's my jam
right there.
...knock‐out tacos in Austin...
That's about as real‐deal
as it goes, man.
...and a funky Asian joint
in Georgia...
Definitely what we look for
on "Triple D."
...where the chef's
doctoring things up...
He's just doing
what he really loves.
...his way.
Keep making food like this,
‐and I'll be back.
‐All right.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins
&amp; Dives."
♪♪♪♪
You go anywhere
in the Southwest,
someone's gonna try to pitch you
on their buddy's taco truck ‐‐
why their taco truck is better,
how their recipes are authentic.
So I'm here to check out
a joint in Austin, Texas,
where two buddies
have taken the taco truck
and put in a strip mall.
This is OneTaco.
Taco norte, coming up.
In Austin, there are
so many options for tacos,
and this place is just
consistently awesome.
Taco jefe ready!
Reminds me of growing up
in Mexico.
FIERI: Just like owners
Tony Avila and Axel Beverido,
who are taking their recipes
straight from the taquerias
of their homeland.
‐Who's the taco aficionado?
‐We both are.
No, you're too skinny to be
taco aficionados, okay?
I look like I could at least
have some legitimacy
in the taco game,
but these two skinny guys?
So, what makes good tacos?
Quality ingredients,
handmade and natural.
I got two Yucatecos.
Right now, I'm eating
Taco Yucateco,
and it just
takes me back home.
It has beans, some meat in it.
It's reliably good every time.
‐What are we making?
‐The Taco Yucateco.
‐Yucateco‐taco‐tuco.
‐Taca‐tucu.
The basis of this dish
is the beans?
Well, the traditional plate has
black beans and the cochinita.
We're just gonna roll it up
in our tortilla.
It's like we're turning a plate
into a taco.
This is like
a magic show!
Water. Regular black beans
that have been picked through.
Six cloves of garlic.
‐Six.
‐Not seven, six.
And an onion. We'll put that on
the burner for about an hour.
Caramelized onions and garlic
going in with some oil.
Stand back, please.
[ Laughs ]
‐These are gonna be pureed?
‐Exactly.
You can come back.
[ Laughs ]
Next order
we're gonna work on?
The cochinita pibil,
which is pork.
Cut it, put it
in a pressure cooker.
Pressure cooker ‐‐
the old Mexican secret.
This is what we're gonna put
inside the pressure cooker
with the pork ‐‐ onions,
fresh squeezed orange juice.
‐Lime juice.
‐Garlic.
Cumin. Oregano.
Pimienta.
Apple cider vinegar.
Salt.
And then the achiote paste.
‐And then we just blend it.
‐Let's see it come together.
Put a bed
of banana leaves here.
So, typically, the banana
leaves work as a barrier
when this is cooking
over an open fire?
Or underground.
‐Yeah, and still keep it moist.
‐Yes, sir.
But primarily, the authenticity
is the flavor factor.
‐That's exactly right.
‐Okay.
‐Dump the mix.
‐There we go.
How long is this gonna go
in the pressure cooker?
About an hour and a half.
And then start shredding it.
I mean, it's just falling apart
right there.
Yeah. Grab a couple
corn tortillas here.
All the corn tortillas
you do in the house?
Yes. Black bean base,
cochinita,
pickled onions with habanero
and bittersweet orange.
Point.
♪♪♪♪
That's about as real‐deal
as it goes, man.
Pork's super tender.
Tortilla is nice
and light.
Little bit of that crema,
a little bit of that fat
coming through
from the beans.
Delicious.
‐Nice job, buddy.
‐Thanks, man.
MAN:
I got two Yucatecos here ready.
The pickled onions on top
make it so delicious.
MAN:
Number two's ready. Campechena.
In the world
of authentic tacos,
which one do they make
you think is the most authentic?
Pastor.
The gringa al pastor.
Why do you call it
"gringa"?
‐The story behind that is ‐‐
‐Here's the story.
There was a female young lady
in Mexico.
Female young lady.
She always wanted her tacos with
cheese and on a flour tortilla.
In Mexico, we don't use
flour tortilla a lot.
We use more corn.
So that kind of turns it
into a gringa, yeah.
So ‐‐ So you're
automatically stereotyping
‐that it's an American female?
‐We are not.
That's the name of the taco.
Yes, you are.
That's what gringa means.
I speak enough Spanish.
‐They're over there.
‐See?
The gringa al pastor
is definitely my favorite.
We have pineapple, onion.
It's a very peculiar spice
that you get into the meat,
‐and it's very good.
‐What's up first?
We're gonna make the flour
tortillas for the gringa pastor.
‐Okay.
‐Flour.
Baking powder.
Salt.
Vegetable shortening.
Water.
Melted butter.
‐So it's all mixed?
‐Yeah, we let it rest
for about an hour or so,
so that it rises.
Put it here.
It's gonna make a hissing sound.
[ Machine whines ]
It's smashing and hitting it
with a little bit of steam
and then shooting it out.
Uh‐huh!
And pre‐cooking.
[ Machine whines ]
There's that sound again.
You're really excited
by that sound.
[ Machine whines ]
[ Imitates whine ]
Flour tortilla's made.
Now we start to build the pork?
Yes.
What are we gonna
marinate it in?
Vinegar. Oregano.
Garlic powder. Pepper.
‐Chile color.
‐"Chile color."
‐Chicken bouillon.
‐Chicken base.
And some cinnamon.
We let it marinate
for like 24 hours.
We get it to like ‐‐
‐I'm sorry. What was that?
‐To do that.
What ‐‐ What was it,
a dance move, or what was this?
We get it to dance
a little bit.
We're gonna have
the pork dancing later.
So what I do is I bring it there
and then rotate it.
Now we're gonna stack it up
on the trompo.
‐Yeah.
‐[ Imitates bass playing ]
We start with
the small pieces first.
‐Wrap them around.
‐You got to hold onto it
so you don't dump‐o
the trompo
and have all the meat
fall on the floor.
I've been waiting
to say it all day.
The pineapple go up on top, and
it will go to the rotisserie.
Yes, sir. Trying to find
the toasty spots right there.
This is the key part
of the gringa.
Holy quesadilla is
what you're talking about.
You put it in here.
Pineapple, onions,
and the cilantro.
I personally do lime.
This is a salsa picada.
It's based with tomatillo
and a lot of chilies.
And you recommend that on here,
as well?
I do.
♪♪♪♪
There is so much flavor...
inside of that taco.
It tastes like you took
a thin‐crust, oven‐fried pizza
of Canadian bacon
and pineapple
and hit it
with some Mexican spices.
It's cheesy and creamy
and meaty,
and then you get
that very reminiscent flavor
of the pineapple,
and then this nice,
really beautiful tortilla.
It's like where the taco truck
and the pizza parlor meet.
‐Delicious.
‐Thank you.
‐Gringas for you.
‐The flavor is just awesome.
WOMAN:
The flour tortilla is soft,
and the meat is just
the right seasoning.
Taco ‐‐ ready.
I love what you guys are doing.
You're taking it really serious.
The attitude is correct.
‐Nice job, buddy.
‐Thanks, man.
FIERI:
Up next, in Smyrna, Georgia...
Aah!
...a tip from my man
G. Garvin...
I can't stop talking
about this place.
...turns out to be
a true hidden treasure.
That right there is money.
So, I'm right outside
of Atlanta, Georgia,
with my buddy ‐‐
Dude, you're gonna
love this place.
It's got
the amazing sushi.
‐With my buddy G. Garvin.
‐I mean, the fresh stuff.
It's got ramen,
all different kinds of ramen.
The broth is amazing.
It's the Asian
chicken wings.
You got to see
what this guy's doing here.
Guy, come on, man!
What are you doing?
It better be good.
This is Yakitori Jinbei.
Come on! My man!
Baby, let's go!
Gyoza.
MAN: When you come here,
and you're inviting someone,
they're like, "Oh, my gosh."
That's it.
This is the best ramen
in the city.
Dude, I can't stop talking
about this place.
He has been ranting
like this in the car.
"Dah, dah, dah, dah, dah, dah."
On and on and on.
Thank you, thank you.
Oh, Jae himself,
he's a character.
He's just like
one of these dishes here ‐‐
little fusion of everything.
FIERI:
Which includes Jae Choi.
Growing up a Chicago kid
in a Korean household
and having a totally
different career.
He was my optometrist
until he decided
to open a restaurant instead.
Since high school, I wanted
to go to culinary school.
As any immigrant parents
would be, they said,
"We didn't come to America
so you could cook."
And if they met him,
they would say,
"Don't hang out with people like
G. Garvin and Guy Fieri."
"Who's that guy?"
Bulgogi beef bowl.
FIERI:
So you bought out a restaurant.
‐I inherited the name.
‐Why didn't you change
the name on the sign?
This was first the test kitchen,
and then it kind of
grew into this.
You hadn't really committed yet,
and by the time
you realized that you were
doing good with it,
‐you couldn't change the name.
‐Exactly.
He's just doing
what he really loves.
‐This is my style.
‐Oh, my gosh.
Spicy wing bowl.
The food is just excellent,
whether it's the spicy
fried chicken
or it's a nice curry ramen.
Katsu curry ramen.
Today, I'm having
the katsu curry ramen.
MAN: Basically, fried pork
over ramen noodles
with a pork‐and‐chicken broth.
Delicious.
Some of the best I ever had.
So, what are
we making first?
We're making a broth
for the katsu curry ramen.
Ramen, man,
it's all about the broth.
This is gonna be
interesting.
So, we got pork
and chicken bones.
Pre‐boiled, washed.
Is that a traditional method
that you learned as a kid
versus just you putting
your doctor thing to it?
It's my scientific doctor
trying to make sure
that the broth
comes out nice and white.
‐Next up?
‐We're gonna bag the kombu.
Dried anchovies.
Bonito flakes.
We're gonna take it out
after a little bit of time.
So you want to temper
that flavoring a little bit?
Yes. So, we got pulverized
shiitake mushrooms.
Tying your shoe's not ever been
a big thing, has it?
That's why they do
the Velcro shoes?
Oh, my gosh.
Help us.
Roasted leeks.
Roasted onions.
Roasted garlic.
Some roasted ginger.
‐How long?
‐18 hours.
‐Oh!
‐We add salt,
sugar,
and fish powder,
and then let it go
for another six.
‐What's the next step?
‐The pork katsu.
Start off with a whole loin
of pork loin.
A whole loin
of pork loin?
I, I see, see
what you're saying, saying.
Thank you. Thank you.
Take this
and tenderize it.
This guy's got little
tricks of the trade.
♪♪♪♪
Salt it a little bit.
Dredge it in AP flour.
Put it into the egg wash.
‐What do you have in there?
‐Tempura flour and water.
‐Dredge it in panko.
‐And this will fry.
350.
The broth is ready.
‐Okay.
‐Smells good.
‐And the noodles.
‐There we go.
Take the pork.
[ Crunching ]
Boy, that sounds crunchy.
Top this with some cabbage
sautéed in some oil and salt.
And we will add that.
Carrots and corn.
‐Never had corn in ramen.
‐Green onions.
You and G. Garvin have been
friends for all these years,
and yet you've chosen
to make just me a bowl of ramen.
G., I'll tell you
how it is.
Tell me.
Mmm.
I can't say that I've ever
had curry ramen broth.
It is a spin on a Japanese dish
called katsu curry.
It takes ramen
another step.
Yeah, the flavor
on that broth is insane.
And I love the little carrots
and corn.
‐It's good.
‐It's not traditional.
It's unique,
and it's funky.
Noodles are tender.
Broth is rich.
And the creativity is an A.
Nice job.
Broth is really smooth,
like a really silky texture.
The crunch of the pork on top
is just perfect.
Outside of Japan,
this is the best.
‐How did you find it?
‐He's a friend of ours.
‐We're eye doctors.
‐You're eye doctors ‐‐
What is this, where all
the eye doctors hang out?
[ Laughter ]
We used to practice together.
Are you still all practicing,
or did you start a pizza place?
No, he's more courageous
than I am.
Just between you and me,
is he better optometrist
or chef?
The food is just amazing.
I think he should just
stay in the restaurant business.
[ Laughter ]
CHOI: Okonomiyaki pork.
What else you got
up your sleeve?
‐Now ‐‐
‐All right, no, no.
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
All right, here's the deal.
Hanging out with my man
G. Garvin in Atlanta
at a funky joint
that just kept the sign
because it was up there.
[ Laughter ]
We'll see you in a bit.
G., I'm finishing this off.
You stand back right now.
Are you still
practicing?
‐A little bit.
‐Here in the back?
"I'm here for
the lunch sushi roll,
and let me check out
your eyes."
Yep.
[ Laughs ]
Welcome back, "Triple D,"
hanging out right
outside of Atlanta, Georgia,
with the one and only
G. Garvin.
G. Garvin!
We're at a funky joint
called Yakitori Jinbei.
G. Garvin's optometrist says
he wants to open a restaurant.
G. says, "Don't do it."
He says, "Don't worry. I got
a place that's closed down.
I'm going to go do
some test kitchen in there."
People come in and eat.
He says, "You know what?
Just turn the old sign back on."
He just adopted the name.
That is the weirdest thing
I've ever heard.
It's like a speakeasy
for, like, Korean‐type bar food
or just, you know, Asian fusion.
CHOI: Korean fried chicken,
table three.
The traditional double‐fried
Korean fried chicken
has a little bit of the sweet,
a little bit of the spicy.
Delicious.
I couldn't find any good
Korean fried chicken,
so I just decided
to make one myself.
What is good Korean
fried chicken?
It's got to have sweet,
heat, and garlic.
‐Okay.
‐We got some chicken here.
‐We're gonna chop this up.
‐Aah!
Hit it with a little bit
of salt and pepper,
and we're gonna make dredge.
All‐purpose flour,
corn starch.
Performing all week.
‐Curry powder.
‐Wait, wait, wait, wait.
There's no way
that's in Korean dish.
[ Laughter ]
Put the flour mixture.
So a little bit
sticks to the chicken.
Ooh, you got
corn starch in this.
Corn starch, all‐purpose flour,
and the curry,
and we make it
into a slurry.
You told me
this was legit.
This is legit Jae Choi.
‐And just dunk and drop.
‐Yes, sir.
Next step.
The sauce for our
Korean fried chicken.
All right. Next, I'm gonna put
in some American barbecue sauce.
‐You never know.
‐So, we got ketchup.
Okay, that's close.
Corn syrup, sugar,
soy sauce.
Doctor.
[ Laughs ]
‐Water.
‐Pew!
‐Capsaicin.
‐So just pure heat?
‐Fresh garlic.
‐How did you end up getting
your eyes worked on
from him, G.?
GARVIN:
He's an amazing guy.
Korean chili pepper.
And last but not least,
gochujang.
One of my favorites.
It's the Korean ketchup, baby.
We'll let it sit
for about two to three days.
To build its flavor.
Okay.
‐Out of the fryer.
‐We're gonna paint it.
Bet you as fast as he can
paint 'em, we can eat 'em.
‐I bet you that.
‐So, we're just gonna build it.
Hit it with some sesame,
green onions.
It's Korean fried chicken.
[ Imitates gunshot ]
♪♪♪♪
Oh, that's crunchy.
‐Mmm.
‐That right there is money.
Even though you brushed
the sauce on there,
it's still
a really good crunch.
Flavored really well.
Sauce has got some heat.
You really
pulled it off, man.
It's nice, man.
Good job.
Korean fried chicken.
Perfectly sweet and spicy
in the right ways.
It's just kind of like
embers of a fire,
so it's really good.
Gyoza. Bulgogi beef bowl.
It's definitely a dive,
and there's nothing like it.
It's just good food,
and everybody's happy.
It's like when I called you, I
said you got to see the passion.
It's definitely what we look for
on "Triple D."
G. knew exactly
where to send me.
You're doing food
the way you like to eat.
That's the beauty of it.
Keep making food like this,
‐and I'll be back.
‐All right.
♪♪♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, a legit
Lebanese spot in Salt Lake...
All day long, buddy.
...wrapping up...
That's almost
a dance move you started.
...and piling on...
I'm gonna pass out
in the car.
...not your everyday flavor.
I'm dying to see
what's gonna happen here.
I do not know
where this is going.
On "Diners, Drive‐Ins, &amp; Dives,"
we're always looking
for funky joints,
you know, mom‐and‐pop joints.
Well, the world
is an ever‐changing place,
which is awesome,
and we found ourselves
at Seven Bites in Orlando,
Florida, at a mom and mom joint.
So here we are,
downtown Salt Lake City,
to check out
a pop and pop joint.
Oh, yeah.
They're doing Lebanese food
with a nice American twist.
This is Laziz Kitchen.
The Shish Tawook wrap.
MAN: Definitely pushes
the ball forward
in the Salt Lake culinary scene.
Salmon and veggie ceviche.
Dishes that I love, that
you can't find anywhere else.
FIERI: 'Cause they're inspired
by the unique backgrounds
of the couple serving them up,
Chef Moudi Sbeity
and his husband, Derek Kitchen.
Me being from Lebanon,
him from Salt Lake,
it's Lebanese food
with a twist.
He makes it better.
FIERI: And he's piling it all on
with this little taste
of everything.
The Mediterranean lunch
has tabbouleh, hummus,
and then it has a kibbeh.
Such a nice combination
of just really nice flavors.
All right, Chef.
Let's get into it.
‐We are making tabbouleh salad.
‐Okay.
Parsley, tomatoes, fresh mint,
quinoa, and green onions.
It usually has
cracked wheat,
but in order to make this
gluten‐free,
we've added quinoa
in there instead.
Okay.
Next step?
The stuffing for
the potato kibbeh. Onions.
I've always known kibbeh
to be meat.
This is a vegan version
that you sometimes find
in the country,
but you don't
typically find it.
‐Okay.
‐Garlic, mushroom.
Gives it
that meaty texture.
Add this mixture
with the potatoes.
Pepper, curry,
veggie base,
crushed walnuts,
and parsley.
And set that on the side before
we start making the patties.
‐Got it.
‐This here is boiled potatoes.
‐Okay.
‐Cumin.
‐Veggie base. Curry.
‐Curry.
‐Black pepper.
Crushed pita chips.
‐Nice.
‐Corn starch,
and some water.
I'm dying to see
what's gonna happen here.
I do not know
where this is going.
Knead this really,
really, really well.
Form this
into an egg shape.
‐Okay.
‐Open it up.
Put the stuffing
in there.
Huh.
Seal it all up.
‐Interesting.
‐Yeah. Pat this down.
And then you fry it.
‐What are we making next?
‐We are making a kafta,
which is Lebanon's, like,
favorite meat dish.
So it's not just vegetarian
and vegan here.
‐Oh, no, no. We're everything.
‐Okay.
This is ground beef 90/10.
Diced onions, parsley,
and some tomato paste.
Pepper and salt mixture.
Cumin. Allspice.
Cinnamon.
‐Ground garlic.
‐Fresh garlic?
Yep. Usually, it's weighed out
to 5 ounces.
Really?
That big of a piece?
Yeah. We're just gonna add
some tomatoes and onions.
‐Ready to plate it up?
‐The lunch platter starts
with hummus,
some tabbouleh,
add some rice,
tabbouleh dressing,
which is lemon juice
and olive oil.
‐Okay.
‐The potato kibbeh.
Pita bread.
Pickled cabbage.
Pickled wild cucumbers
that we import from Lebanon.
‐Our kafta here is done.
‐Wow.
I'm gonna pass out
in the car.
♪♪♪♪
Great flavors. Love it
with the onions and tomatoes.
‐I like the char.
‐Uh‐huh.
♪♪♪♪
‐Hummus is great.
‐Thank you.
Silky smooth.
The tabbouleh with the lemon
juice and the olive oil?
that's my jam right there.
The kibbeh.
Flavor's dynamite.
Lot of texture, lot of
seasoning, totally unique.
Here's the beauty of this.
In one plate, you're getting
all different types
of flavors and textures.
All day long, buddy.
Delicious.
The Mediterranean platter
is great.
Like a culinary tour
of Lebanon.
SBEITY: Salad bowl falafel
and grape leaves on the window.
FIERI: And while Moudi's
serving up his specialties,
Derek's serving the community
in another way, as well.
I've been serving
as a city council member,
and recently, I was elected
to the Utah State Senate.
‐Congratulations.
‐Thank you, sir.
MAN #2:
Moudi and Derek just make this
such an inclusive
and fun environment
for everyone to come
and enjoy some amazing food.
Shish Tawook chicken wrap.
MAN #3:
The Shish Tawook chicken wrap ‐‐
That's really one
of my favorites.
It's a complex herbal
and spicy type of a flavor.
Now we are creating
the Shish Tawook chicken mix.
The [Stammering]
Shish Tawook.
Okay.
So we start out with some smoked
paprika. Ground coriander.
White pepper. Cumin goes
in everything Middle Eastern.
‐Pepper and salt.
‐Way to say it backwards.
Canola oil.
Apple cider vinegar.
Crushed garlic.
Traditionally,
this is made with yogurt.
For some of our clients
who can't eat dairy,
we're gonna use
mustard instead.
So you're getting
a little more flavor?
Yep.
Tomato paste.
And then how are
we gonna serve this?
Wrapped in a pita
just like ‐‐
That's almost
a dance move you started.
‐Yeah, just like ‐‐
‐We're doing the pita.
All right. Let it marinate 24
hours. Cook it in the skillet.
‐What's up next?
‐Tahini sauce.
We're gonna start with some
garlic, salt, lemon juice,
and tahini, and that's
just ground‐up sesame seeds.
Add some water.
And you're gonna nuke it.
I mean blend it.
How did you go from "blend"
to "nuke"?
‐I don't know.
‐Now we can put it together?
Yep. We're going to start
with veggies, the chicken,
pickled cabbage,
and wild cucumbers.
We usually add fries in all
of the wraps in Lebanon.
‐Really?
‐Parsley,
pepper and salt,
and this here is called toum.
Toum is a potent
garlic sauce.
About a tablespoon
is five cloves of garlic.
Wow.
The tahini sauce
that we just made,
and then that goes
on the panini press.
‐Oh, really?
‐Yeah.
And we are done.
♪♪♪♪
The pita is nice
and light
and has great
moisture to it.
The balance inside of the wrap
is great.
Lot of bright acidity.
Fresh vegetable flavor
with the cucumbers and tomatoes.
Little crunch
of the cabbage.
This just has a lot of flavors
that are working well together.
‐Mm‐hmm.
‐Delicious.
‐I love the Shish Tawook.
‐It's insane.
A flavor explosion
in your mouth.
SBEITY:
Kafta burger, side salad.
WOMAN: This is one
of my favorite places to visit.
I love Laziz Kitchen.
Food is a common
denominator.
‐It brings people together.
‐Yeah.
And you guys are doing
a fantastic job of it.
‐Thank you very much.
‐Well done, my friend.
‐Yeah, thank you.
‐Congrats.
So that's it for this road trip.
But don't worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins, &amp; Dives."
Just use this knife.
This knife will be a lot easier.
Okay. Chop it.
[ Laughs ]
‐Good. Next slice.
‐Yeah.
[ Both laugh ]