I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Magic man.
...it's burgers...
Hold on.
Get the grinder!
...barbecue...
I don't know that I'm supposed
to eat it or tackle it.
...and plenty of flavor
in between...
So good.
...like at a real-deal
smoke shack in San Antonio...
We're old-school here.
This is a barbecue joint.
...an Asian powerhouse
in Napa...
I can't shove it
in my mouth fast enough.
...and in Little Rock...
One more bite.
...a farm-fresh joint
that will blow your mind.
Like...
That is outstanding.
That's all right here,
right now on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in San Antonio,
Texas, and yes,
ladies and gentlemen,
it is always bigger in Texas.
I'm here to check out a joint.
This guy has got three of them.
He's got a meat market
over here, he's got a bar
and a food truck over there,
and he's also got
this little joint --
The Smoke Shack,
BBQ and Southern Kitchen.
Hey, Guy,
do we got valet here?
Just on the weekends.
[ Laughs ]
Turkey, chicken plate
in the window.
Of all the barbecue joints that
there is in San Antonio,
this is the place to be.
-Brisket grilled cheese.
MAN: Chris grew up in Texas,
so he has a lot of Texas
barbecue influences,
and then he went to college
in the southeast.
FIERI: Where Chris Conger
took the barbecue rig
he got
for high school graduation.
I went to school in Mississippi,
so we've got pork and --
[ Whistles ] You're going
to get us run out of Texas.
You can't do pork in Texas.
We brought pork to Texas.
Don't!
They're going to get mad.
All right, all right,
all right.
Not to worry, he's still got
plenty of Lonestar
shining on his menu.
Two corn chip pies up.
There's nothing more Texas
than corn chip pie.
Brisket mixed in with the beans
and the chips and the cheese.
It's a real treat.
-Corn chip pie.
-Make it happen, captain.
So first, the rub
for the brisket --
salt, and, of course,
black pepper.
Of course.
Chili powder, garlic pepper,
paprika, onion powder,
and brown sugar.
Doing it with a little bit
of your Mississippi attitude
all the way down here
in San Antonio.
That's right.
And how long
is this going to sit?
Four to six hours.
This is going to go
to the smoker now.
12 to 14 hours.
-What do we got to do next?
-Barbecue sauce.
So, ketchup,
apple cider vinegar...
-Some water.
-A whole mess of molasses.
A whole mess.
Some steak sauce.
So, here we have
our mustard sauce,
which has this barbecue
sauce in it, as well.
I'm not going to tell you
how we did that.
Magic man.
You're standing too close
to the smoker, son.
Wash-your-sister sauce.
Worcestershire sauce,
garlic pepper, barbecue rub,
black pepper, honey...
-Darling.
-...and the kicker, cinnamon.
-Doctor.
-Scalpel.
The rest of the industry
uses an immersion blender.
Hey, we're old-school here.
This is a barbecue joint.
What do we got next?
Beans, olive oil, onions,
jalapeños.
We like it spicy in Texas.
Garlic and some
salt and pepper.
Caramelize this down
a little bit.
Add our crushed tomatoes,
add our pinto beans
to the hot water.
We've already boiled these off
once to get the bran off.
Sauté it, spice it.
-Garlic pepper.
-Salt and chili powder.
Let those cook down an hour
and a half to two.
[ Laughs ]
Don't fill up on chips now.
Hey, you should see how much
meat we're going to put on this.
All right.
We're going to put
the cheese on.
After that goes the beans
to melt the cheese.
Yeah, melt the cheese.
Next, we're going to add
our brisket.
This little paper boat doesn't
know what's happening to it.
Top it off
with our barbecue sauce.
The corn chip pie.
Corn chip pie is like pizza --
when it's good,
it's really good, and when
it's bad, it's still good.
This happens to be
on the very good side of things.
The beans have got great flavor,
great texture.
The corn chips just add a nice,
little crunch,
but it's the barbecue
that really sings.
I mean, you took
a pretty simple staple
to a lot of people
who serve at a ball game
and really put
the culinary touch to it.
-Delicious.
-Thanks, man.
Outstanding.
-Corn chip pie.
-Thank you.
The brisket is phenomenal.
A perfect compliment
to the corn chips.
The sauce he puts on top
of the brisket, I love it.
-Best food I ever had.
-Ever?
-Ever.
-Yes, ever.
Wow.
Two of my brothers over here,
we've had quite
a few adventures together.
What else did you try
on the menu?
These ribs -- the meat
just falls off the bone.
FIERI: That's actually what got
me introduced to this place.
We're on a family road trip
and we stop here in San Antonio
to check out
the Buckhorn Saloon...
Aah!
...and some
Grizzly Adams-looking cat
walks in with a bag of ribs.
See, my buddy, Happy,
and his wife,
Elizabeth, own the saloon
and go way back
with Chris' family.
We've known the Congers
for three generations.
We just never realized
how talented they were.
Neither did they.
FIERI: And he's putting a ton of
talent into this mouthful.
Big dog in the window!
The big dog -- there's three
different meats on it.
You better not eat breakfast
and don't plan on eating dinner.
The big dog -- brisket...
Pulled pork and our
house-made hot link.
Give me the rundown.
This is a whole
brisket ground up.
Whole thing.
[ Whistles ]
Curing salt, coriander,
black pepper, allspice,
cayenne -- there's the heat --
fine sea salt...
-Okay.
-...red chili flakes...
-Lots of garlic.
-...and really cold water.
Drop it in, case it out.
Smoke them 20
to 30 minutes on 200.
All right, next up?
Mustard sauce for
the pulled pork.
Come on, gambler.
-Creole mustard...
-A lot of honey.
...apple cider vinegar,
our barbecue sauce,
Worcestershire, barbecue rub,
and the secret ingredient.
-What is it?
-It looks like blackberry jelly.
Raspberry jelly.
Almost, Guy.
There you go.
I like the vinegar, I like
a little bit of the sweet.
-Excellent.
-We got the pork pulled.
Here's our all-beef
hot link.
A little on the other side
with brisket.
-That is good hot link.
-Thank you, sir.
Mustard sauce on the pork.
Brisket gets the barbecue sauce.
Top it with a little slaw.
Oh, yeah, feta cheese
in this slaw.
-You what?
-Yep.
There you go -- big dog.
I don't know that I'm supposed
to eat it or tackle it.
♪♪
It's one of those
excessive-type sandwiches
from the description
and the appearance,
but I got to be honest
with you, these are fine.
Slaw's got a nice,
little finishing touch to it,
that little brininess,
the acidity of that feta,
those barbecue sauces
really play well together.
The hot link is dynamite,
and it's the kind of thing
that I think you'd order,
eat half of,
and then be thrilled to have
the rest for dinner.
-Yeah.
-Nice job.
Big dog, side of fries.
Being in Texas,
it's everything that we like.
It has a great mustard sauce
to along with this pork.
Which isn't something you
typically find in San Antonio.
-No, it's not.
-It's the only place.
All right, let's make
these plates look pretty.
The Smoke Shack --
you just can't beat it.
You're not just another
pretty face.
Hey, there's something
under this.
Watch out for this guy.
Free gym membership
for every time you visit.
FIERI: Up next, a farm-to-table
spot in Little Rock...
I got to tell you,
I love it already.
...getting meticulous
with the meat...
You're really kind of taking
this to a ridiculous level,
you understand?
...and spreading Southern charm
on their burgers.
You better bring an appetite
on that one.
Aggggh! Errrrt!
[ Laughs ]
Psych!
Wow.
We're here in Little Rock,
Arkansas,
to check out a joint that
started as an ice cream shop,
and, man, has it morphed
into a community-minded
farm-to-table cafe
that everybody loves.
This is The Root.
♪♪
Spicy fried chicken!
Order up!
It's kind of unique.
It's got it's own charm.
It's just a flavorful place,
inside and out,
the food and the people.
FIERI: It's what you get when
people play by their own rules,
like husband-and-wife team
Jack and Corri Sundell,
who've been taking the food biz
and DIY to a whole new level.
You are two
interesting people.
The stacker washer and dryer
on the kitchen line.
-We wash our napkins.
-We fold them and everything.
I've been to 1,200-plus
"Triple-D" joints.
That's a first.
Did I drive up and see
three storage containers?
We needed to expand.
And the conventional method of
nails and a hammer and wood...
-Not our style.
-Not your's?
I got to tell you,
I love it already.
FIERI: And their menu isn't just
run-of-the-mill either.
CORRI: It's all farm-to-table,
locally-sourced.
MAN: If you're vegan, you can
find something on the menu,
and if you love
a good cheeseburger,
they got that also.
-Pimento cheeseburger!
Blended cheese and peppers,
a little spice.
Kind of a good Southern dish
that I really like.
This is the pimento cheese
for our pimento cheeseburger.
Great.
We've got cheddar
and Pepper Jack.
-It's not local cheese.
-Wha?!
We're waiting for that
cheddar producer
to come along knocking.
We're looking for cheddar!
Cream cheese, garlic mayo
we make in house.
-I like it.
-Fire-roasted bell peppers,
sriracha,
smoke-dried Marconi peppers,
sambal, fresh-chopped parsley.
-Okay.
So, we're just going to
get things started,
watching to see that cream
cheese get fully incorporated.
That's looking good.
There's just that little kick
of that sriracha,
a little kick
of that sambal,
a little of that smokiness
of that pepper coming through.
Now we're going to grind
the meat for the burger.
We get a whole cow at a time
from a farm at --
There is no way you can get
a whole cow through --
-Oh, you cube it up.
-Yeah.
-That makes more sense.
-It's a process.
Okay, so you bring
a whole cow in.
It's impressive.
Never seen that before.
Today we've got sirloin
and some fattier trim pieces.
To make sure that you get the
fat and the flavor combination.
Do course the first time
through.
Now we're going to sprinkle
smoked Marconi peppers,
then we're going to put it
through for the second grind.
When we originally opened,
we thought we were going
to grind beef to order.
"Two burgers? Hold on.
Get the grinder!
Yeah, we got this!"
Now we're going
to patty it up?
Make sure it's even,
pull that ring,
handle it as little
as possible.
It got it.
Onto the flat top.
We got our sweet potatoes
going in.
And the burger to flip?
Pimento cheese,
and it's game time.
So, here we've got
our savory butter bun.
Savory butter bun.
Our house garlic mayo.
Everything comes
with a big salad?
That's right.
You know, the yin and yang.
This is a traditional 14-day
sweet pickle
that we make here
in house.
Slide the burger on here.
-House-made garlic vinaigrette.
-Okay.
We got our sweet
potato fries ready.
That's it.
The thing's heavy.
Definitely got to hunch
on this one.
Mm. The ground beef has got
fantastic texture.
The grind size,
the griddle temp,
the caramelization,
great bun choice.
The pickle is
definitely needed.
That balances out.
Got a lot of richness
and delicious pimento cheese.
I didn't know it was going to be
a whole patty of pimento.
You better bring an appetite
on that one.
SERVER: Pimento cheeseburger.
It's the best burger
in town.
As soon as I ate it, taste buds
went through the roof.
It's like, "Wow!"
So much labor in everything
you're doing. Why?
Because we're so focused
on local foods,
we want to get
scratch ingredients
because that's what the farmers
have to sell to us.
I love this.
I mean, I applaud this.
Every day you're in here,
you're going to see a farmer.
Coming in, making deliveries.
-I'm a local organic farmer.
-Okay.
A restaurant that sources
primarily local food,
that was huge.
That's part of why
it's all so delicious.
All right, what are we
going to make next, brother?
Old-world bratwurst.
Hang on.
Don't tell me about it.
We're hanging out
at The Root Cafe
We're in Little Rock, Arkansas.
When we come back,
we're making the bratwurst
with the crazy guy.
Old-world brat.
It's the way a brat
should be made.
FIERI: "I'll take a brat
with sauerkraut."
"It's 8:30 in the morning."
"Okay, I'll take two then."
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple-D."
Hanging out in Little Rock,
Arkansas, at The Root Cafe,
a full-scratch menu focusing on
local farms and local producers
that is crazy.
WOMAN: It's got a good spirit.
It's got a good energy.
When they put it together,
they have an artist side.
FIERI: And definitely
a chef's taste buds.
It's delicious comfort food,
but it has a special,
little twist.
Old-world bratwurst.
It's the way a brat
should be made.
I like the sauerkraut.
That's my favorite part.
FIERI: What are
we going to make?
We are casing
fresh bratwurst today.
So, we have the ground
pork shoulder.
We're going to add kosher salt,
white pepper,
ground ginger, nutmeg,
mix it
a little bit to get
the spices incorporated,
whisk up
these farm-fresh eggs,
and we're going to stir those
into our heavy cream.
Interesting.
Pull it out.
We're going to go to case.
We'll pick the sausages and then
we'll twist them into links.
Grill it to get that color
on the sides,
and then we're going to
throw it in the oven
and give it about 30 minutes
to finish at a low temp.
While that works,
we make kraut.
This is lacto-fermented,
homemade sauerkraut.
So, we'll add in
our cabbage.
I mean, you're really kind of
taking this
to a ridiculous level,
you do understand?
We got to set ourselves
apart somehow.
The setting-yourself-apart
factor has happened
a long time ago.
Kosher salt, caraway seed.
Pound and stir, and that's
going to help
get a little of that liquid
to come out
and make a brine
with the salt.
How long is this
all going to get working?
Three to four weeks in the
summer when it's warmer to...
Hold on!
I got places to go!
Can I ask what
the goldfish water is for?
-And where's the goldfish?
-Where's my goldfish?
[ Mumbling ]
Now we'll put our plate
on top here,
and we're going to drop
the brine bag.
That'll give us the seal
around the edges here.
Then we're going
to cover it.
Around 4 weeks,
and we'll have
your old-world
bratwurst ready for you.
Let's go get the other one out
of the back and make this brat.
I don't got 4 weeks.
I got stuff to do.
Pot of boiling water here.
It's heated up in
the water now.
We'll just give it
a little sear.
And now we're gong
to dress the bun.
House garlic mayo,
Dijon on the bottom.
Throw that on here
for a minute.
Can you see all the fat
and all the juice
and all the flavor
that's built inside of that?
The key to this is not to break
this casing
and let all
that flavor come out.
That's beautiful.
House-made kraut.
We put that on there cold.
That's our old-world
bratwurst.
♪♪
Delicious.
Can I just have a bowl of kraut.
♪♪
Awesome. I am not kidding you,
it's so fantastic.
The grind of the meat --
spot on.
Casing -- nice, little snap.
Bun -- light, but sturdy
enough to hold it
'cause there's a lot of juice
coming out of that.
I mean, you're tasting the pork,
you're getting
the real flavors of it.
I'm not kidding.
The kraut -- that's what
puts it over the top.
That is outstanding.
Like...
One more bite.
Old-world brat.
Order up.
It's pretty juicy,
so you bite into it,
you get that juice
coming out.
It's snappy.
The sauerkraut is
the perfect crispness
and it's got
the perfect sourness.
-Got a Root Benny.
-It's just cool.
You come here and you feel
like you're at home.
So many people talked about
coming here,
said the food's really good,
you care a lot
about what you're doing,
really love your community.
Now that I get here and I see
how funkalicious it is,
I'm sold.
Coming up, a tiny Asian joint
in Napa, California...
It's a lot of little
small kitchen
for us all to be
all over here.
...going huge with the ramen...
I want to eat it
till I pass out.
...and kicking fried rice
into high gear.
If this was a car movie,
this would be
"The Fast and Delicious."
♪♪
Welcome to another edition
of "Neighborhood Eats."
Today, we're at my
Aunt Etna's house
where she makes a fanta--
Nah, I'm just kidding.
No, this is "Triple D"
and we're actually
in Napa, California,
to check out a funky
little Asian joint
that is small on size,
but big on flavor.
Remember it's E-I-G,
not A-T-E --
this is
Eight Noodle Shop.
Beef ramen coming up!
Eight Noodle is such a fabulous,
interesting place.
-Korean wings!
-It's Asian fusion.
FIERI: Served up by owner
David Lu,
who's bringing a lifetime
of experience to the table.
I was born
and raised in Taiwan.
-Oh, really?
-I moved here when I was nine.
My family owned Chinese
restaurants when we moved here.
FIERI: And when he set up
this shop,
he mixed in even more
Asian influence.
So it's not
a strict Chinese.
-Nope.
-It's not Thai.
-It's not Japanese.
It's across the board.
LU: Kimchi bacon fried rice,
pick up!
The kimchi fried rice
is amazing.
You can tell it's fresh and
they took their time to make it.
-All right, Chef, first step.
-Beef cheeks...
Seared off.
Next step?
-Mirepoix.
-Sesame oil?
Whole garlic,
ginger, carrots,
celery, parsley,
thyme, onion.
And this is all just
for the brazing liquid?
That's correct.
Tomato, give it
a little richness.
A little brown sugar.
-Soy sauce?
-Veal stock.
-That you make in house.
-Correct.
Add the cheeks to it.
How long in the oven?
-Hour, hour-and-a-half.
-Okay. Next?
Kimchi -- onions, ginger,
garlic, Korean spice...
-That's the key.
-...fish sauce.
-So this is the base.
-Now we're over here.
It's a lot of little
small kitchen for us
to be all over here.
Water.
Rice flour -- gives it a little
thickness on the kimchi.
-Okay. Next?
-Salted cabbage.
-Salted napa cabbage.
-Ginger.
Now if you're not in Napa,
can you use other cabbage?
Sorry.
Rice wine vinegar, garlic,
red bell pepper.
-A little sugar.
-Daikon.
A bunch of it.
More of the Korean spice.
The rice flour mixture.
Pour this on top of it,
look at that.
We got the kimchi jar.
And these are the weights
to press it down.
LU: Correct, for 10 days.
Luke, I am your kimchi.
Sorry.
I heard the echo.
Let's make some fried rice.
All right.
Pan sauce, sesame oil.
Pre-cooked,
cooled-down white rice.
Correct.
A little kimchi,
pickled mushrooms.
And then pickled
daikon radish and carrots.
And carrots, a little garlic,
a little ginger.
Everybody back on.
♪♪
Whoa!
That kimchi is so good though.
LU: We're going to go with
a little shredded cabbage,
carrot, little bacon.
-Okay.
Then we got
the secret sauce next.
Sauce you make in house?
Correct.
Bring that up.
So fried rice, beef cheeks,
a little green onions.
There you go.
♪♪
I think that most fried rice
is pretty pedestrian.
If this was a millennial car
movie, this would be
"The Fast and Delicious."
[ Laughs ]
Textures are awesome,
depth of flavor is amazing.
Tang, acid, salt,
a little bit of the heat,
the crunch, the tender --
I can't stuff it
in my mouth fast enough.
The beef cheeks sing,
but the real kicker here
is the kimchi
and the pickled veggies
and the pickled mushrooms.
-Dynamite, bro.
-Thank you.
And I'm sorry I had
to drop the chopsticks.
I had to get busy
with a fork.
-[ Chuckles ]
-Mm!
-Kimchi fried rice.
-Thank you.
That's beautiful, crisp, fresh.
The spice is good.
I love it.
We got a chicken
and egg shrimp rice.
The fact that they can make
a wide variety of flavors
out of that little kitchen
is pretty impressive.
The whole building
is 1,000 square feet?
Not counting the patio,
the whole building
is 1,000 square feet.
FIERI: But that's not holding
them back
when it comes to
scratch-making the staples.
Pork ramen, pick up!
You're going to open a funky
little joint like this,
you need
to make your own ramen.
Absolutely.
Did you guys make ramen at home
when you were a kid?
-We made ramen by hand.
-Really?
Mom made
hand-cut noodles.
All right, so give me
the rundown.
-AP flour.
-"All-purpose."
Water, liquid smoke.
-In the noodles?
-Gives it a little smokiness.
Potassium
carbonated water.
Oh, that's what
I thought it was.
Gives it a little
carbonation.
Pinch of salt,
add more water.
-To get the right consistency.
-Correct.
When it comes out, it goes
in the walk-in overnight.
-All right.
-So we're making our pork broth.
It's not every restaurant
that you go to in Napa,
you're going to just go
walk down and say,
"Hey, by the way you taking
that pig hoof
and cooking it up
yourself?
-Into the hot water.
-Roasted chicken bones.
Low heat, overnight.
Next day, we add kombu.
Seaweed.
Rice wine vinegar, green onions,
onions, celery, tomato, garlic.
-Think that's enough?
-Carrot. Ginger.
Tamari.
Bonito fish flakes.
So this is going to cook down
for how long now?
Hour and a half.
And that's the foundation
of the ramen broth.
-Correct.
-Okay, drop the noodle,
then we'll put it together.
-Okay.
Pork back fat puree,
our noodles, our broth.
Oh, you're my broth-er.
[ Laughs ] Get it.
He's my brother,
but he was doing the br--
he's my broth --
No?
Okay.
All right, sorry.
Our pulled pork, our belly,
arugula, baby spinach...
Not something you typically see
when you get ramen.
...a little bit of bamboo,
toasted sesame seeds,
finish it off
with a little scallion.
♪♪
We also offer a house-made
chili oil --
spice it up a little bit.
Now we're talking.
Mm.
-So I'm going to get in.
-Don't do it, Guy.
I love the arugula
and the spinach.
At my restaurant, Chicken Guy!,
we say, "Sauce is the boss."
But here at Eight Noodle,
broth is the "bossth."
[ Laughs ]
I like that.
Huh?
It's delicious.
I want to eat it
until I pass out.
So good.
Here's the pork ramen.
The noodles are wonderful,
very well-made.
The broth is just mouthwatering.
Shrimp rice, pick up!
Eight noodle
is just perfect food.
It's a place of its own.
This place might be small,
but the flavor's huge.
-Nicely done, my friend.
-Thank you.
Nicely done.
So that's it for this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
But don't you worry,
there's funky joints
all over this country.
And I'll be looking for you
next week on "Triple D."
Hey, Guy, what about trading
650 horsepower
for this bull-power
right here?
-Done deal, buddy.
-Only in Texas.
One born every day.
Hey, where exactly
is reverse on this?
Well, I don't know.
I got my ride, you got that one.
-[ Laughs ]
-Whoo-hoo!
♪♪