You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy. That place
you went to in that one town
"that served that one dish,
how are they doing after
'Triple-D?'"
You know what? I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
because "Triple-D"
joints have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking,
like on this trip.
Do you guys think at home
I want a fork?
Absolutely not.
A neighborhood diner
in Denver, Colorado...
Where's my California
representation, huh?
What's up with that?
...cooking up favorites
from all over the nation...
Prime time.
...in Nashville, Tennessee,
a food truck
putting down roots...
Was that? Nah.
...and upping their grilled
cheese game...
Way to rock the house.
...a family seafood joint
still going strong in Miami...
Nothing wrong with that.
...and in
Northern California...
This has changed dramatically
from when I came here as a kid.
...I'm letting you all in
on a Fieri family secret.
That's sandwich technology, son.
Old friends, new places and more
off-the-hook flavors...
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple-D Nation."
So Hunter and I are about
an hour north of Sacramento,
where Interstate 5
hits Highway 20.
Now, Hunter, when I was a kid,
we would come through here
and stop at this place,
and it was just
a little sandwich counter.
Now, it's a sandwich counter
and a restaurant
and a sports bar,
and then they throw in gelato,
and they got their own bakery,
and they got a gift shop
you would not forget.
Now, the name of the town
is Williams,
but they should really call it
Granzella's.
♪♪
MAN: Muffaletta!
Go to Granzella's
for the experience,
but definitely stay
for the food.
Classic sandwiches here
are amazing.
FIERI: Now, you've never seen
this joint on "Triple-D,"
but when I was a kid,
we stopped here every year
during road trips to Tahoe.
Order for Kyle!
FIERI:
So now I'm letting you in on
one of my favorite
family traditions.
This has changed dramatically
from when I came here as a kid.
They got a grocery store now.
I don't think I've ever
been here before.
You have been here.
I swear.
When?
We went dirt bike riding, and we
came here on the way back.
Might have been too small
to remember, now.
That looks good.
Granzella's opened back in 1976.
-How you been, man?
-Nice to see you.
Long time no see.
And this is the man,
Dino McCarty, whose grandfather,
Jim Granzella,
started the joint.
Over the years, we got
many generations of the family
that are here, aunts and uncles
and cousins and sisters,
hustling to make this run.
We're on a road trip,
and we were just --
We're driving through,
and they said,
"Where do you want
to stop and eat?"
And I go, "Oh, Granzella's
is right around,
you know, coming off the 20."
So we made it.
You're here.
Sorry for the short notice,
but thanks for having us.
Yeah.
Tell us what we should get.
The muffaletta sandwich
is really good.
The muffaletta you guys
are known for, though.
Yeah.
FIERI: And muffaletta
just ain't muffaletta
without the olive salad,
which these guys
make from scratch.
McCARTY:
We use a blend of giardiniera,
Sicilian olives,
Kalamata olives, sliced garlic,
Greek peppers, seasoning,
which gives it some nice zesty
flavor, canola, and olive oil.
Now we're gonna go through
the processor,
do a nice smooth grind.
My grandfather and grandmother
started this recipe
35 years ago.
We're one of the largest
distributors
in the state of California
for muffaletta.
♪♪
This has a rich, briny,
garlicky flavor
that goes well
with all the deli meats.
Use Genoa salami,
Italian mortadella,
which is a bologna
and provolone cheese.
That's the muffaletta.
So this is the chopped-up olive
and vegetable spread.
I find this a lot
in New Orleans.
Mmm. It's all that pickled veg
and all that crunch.
Yeah.
This is what I remember
getting when I was a kid.
Oh, yeah.
-But we'd get get a huge one.
-That is good.
And I would eat it halfway
on the way up to Tahoe
and then eat it the next day.
What I like is,
when you bite it,
it doesn't all
come out the back.
[ Laughs ]
That's sandwich technology, son.
That is ridiculous.
And how many different
sandwiches you guys do?
30.
Is that a Reuben?
That is the Reuben,
and that's on the marble rye.
Been making this sandwich
over 40 years now.
It's one of our best sellers.
So a Reuben is mayonnaise,
mustard, pickles,
peppers and traditional
corned beef
and sauerkraut, Swiss cheese.
We throw that in the panini,
and that's a Reuben.
♪♪
You got after that.
[ Laughs ]
A lot of time, on a Reuben,
if you don't have
a really good sauerkraut,
it overpowers the sandwich,
and this doesn't.
Got a little bit pickle
in there, a lot of cheese.
♪♪
-This just wrecked it.
-[ Laughs ]
This just wrecked
my whole Granzella's visit.
I was always fine just
with the muffaletta.
MAN: The grilled Reuben.
That light rye bread is crunchy
but soft in the middle.
Sauerkraut with the corned beef
is really good.
FIERI: But these sandwiches were
almost a thing of the past.
And this is the fire.
When did the fire happen?
2007, October 11th,
burnt down the whole building.
It was such a loss
for the community,
but we got it back
and operational
in less than a year.
Opened July of 2008,
nine months later.
Turned the whole thing
over that fast?
Yeah.
Well, it's because
the whole community
needed you to come back.
-Yeah.
One of my best friends,
Paul Thompson.
[ Laughs ]
How many years ago
was it we came here together?
I want to say almost 10.
Okay, so how legit is the food?
Oh, the food is fantastic.
How would you describe
Granzella's?
Granzella's is a bunch of
"Triple-D" joints in one.
You got the gelato.
You got the bakery.
You've got the deli.
You've got the lunch.
You got the bar.
You can watch some sports there.
You can grab some stuff to go.
It's got everything
all in one package.
It's a one-stop shop.
If you try to go bleaching
your hair
and you try to take my show,
I'm gonna take you out.
Oh, well, don't worry.
It won't grow anyways.
♪♪
Your family has got to be
so proud of you.
Absolutely. Thank you.
Yeah.
I mean, you stick
to the quality.
It's what I remember
just on a bigger scale.
What do you think, bud?
I'm coming back here for sure
on the way back.
-[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
Can I get about 10 of these
to go, though?
[ Laughs ]
You know what?
I'll bet this place will still
be jamming years from now
when Hunter and Ryder
take their kids on a road trip.
Now, next up in Nashville...
Here comes the good stuff.
FIERI: ...what started as
a crazy food truck...
I've never seen that.
...has turned into
a grilled cheese emporium.
That is so good.
I'm gonna go into, like,
a little dream sequence.
Back in Nashville, Tennessee,
I checked out a funky food truck
that was going gangster
with their grilled cheese,
and anyone who is
anyone ate there.
Was that? Nah.
Well, eventually the line
got so long,
the truck wasn't enough,
and they had to set up shop
in a brick-and-mortar.
This is The Grilled Cheeserie.
♪♪
We have two macs on the grill.
Saw Grilled Cheeserie
on "Triple-D,"
ran down to the truck
after I watched it.
They're so fresh
and just unique.
The grilled cheese
is not just for kids.
It's for everybody.
FIERI: That's exactly what
owners Crystal De Luna-Bogan
and her husband, Joseph,
had in mind when they opened
this meal on wheels in 2010.
We're the place where
grilled cheeses are made.
We're the place that dreams
about grilled cheeses
are fulfilled.
All right.
So what are you gonna make?
Pimento mac and cheese.
We got some Tennessee cheddar.
That's a monster!
We're gonna cut this up,
shred it up.
There weren't a lot of food
trucks on "Triple-D."
So we really felt like,
"Wow, we, like,
made some kind of impact
this far."
FIERI: So cheese is done.
We're going to make some mayo --
eggs, garlic,
a spice mix and then --
-Hot sauce?
-...hot sauce and then the oil.
-Slow stream.
Oh, stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
He was like, "You're gonna
spill oil everywhere."
We just drilled
a little hole in it.
Oh, I'm ripping that off
for sure.
Did you guys see this,
so it does its own slow stream?
It's breakage-proof.
He went on and on about it.
He was taking pictures
with his phone.
He was, like, sending video
to I don't know who.
I've never seen that.
It was so fun.
Like, I was laughing
the whole time.
So we got our mac,
and here comes the good stuff.
We got our cheese.
Righteous.
Now, we're just gonna add
our roasted peppers.
So that's basically it.
-Okay.
-Assembly time.
Pimento mac and cheese,
some of our beautiful
local tomatoes, bacon bits,
and then we finish it off
with the same cheddar
that we just sliced.
Then we press it down.
-Cut it on halfway.
-Uh-huh.
Yeah.
-That's how you do it.
-It is so good.
I'm gonna go into, like,
a little dream sequence.
And I wasn't the only one
singing their praises that day.
Trace Adkins
at a grilled cheeserie?
The thing about being
in Nashville is,
country music singers,
they just come up to a food
truck to get some food.
It's surreal.
This is gourmet
right here, man.
House-made pimento cheese,
local cheddar, macaroni...
He reads the menu
of a food truck
and makes it sound
like a country song.
And they finally put down roots,
opened a brick-and-mortar
near Music Row.
That means more grilled-up
goodness,
like their cheesed-up
take on a classic French dip.
We do a really beautiful,
medium-rare roast beef.
We season with salt
and fresh cracked pepper,
and then we lay it
on a bed of onions,
herbs, garlic, and then
we roast it in the oven.
And we slice it real thin
for the sandwich.
FIERI:
And then, assembly time.
We start with really
well-buttered sourdough,
Swiss cheese, roast beef,
horseradish aioli,
French onions, which is onions,
shallots, salt, pepper,
and then we deglaze it with
sherry and Worcestershire sauce.
Then we crisp it
with a weight on it,
and then we serve it with roast
beef au jus dipping sauce.
Their meat is juicy.
It's got a great au jus.
The sweetness of the onions
and the heat from
the horseradish, it's perfect.
FIERI:
Another one topping the charts,
a highbrow turkey melt
called the turkey di parma.
DE LUNA-BOGAN: We have beautiful
local buttermilk cheddar,
shaved roasted turkey,
pesto aioli.
Then we do a layer
of sun-cured tomatoes,
another piece
of buttermilk cheddar,
and then we sprinkle
some Parmigiano-Reggiano
and then lay the sandwich
right on top of the cheese.
It's delicious.
It's grilled to perfection,
and it doesn't feel heavy
when you bite into it.
It has that really
good crust on it.
The sun-dried tomatoes,
they give it
a nice kind of zesty kick to it.
We leave it
a little bit chunky.
Because it's funky
when it's chunky, isn't it?
The food truck
is alive and well,
and we have a brand-new
one that is rolling out.
We're building two more
restaurants this year.
We feel really good about
what we've set up.
I'm telling you what.
You're gonna get a truck
from California,
drive it to Nashville,
husband-and-wife team,
and you're gonna rock
this out,
you better be delivering it
with something this righteous.
Mm, awesome job.
-Thank you.
-Way to rock the house.
Thank you, sir.
[ Cheering ]
♪♪
And not to mention,
they're pretty much always voted
the best food truck
in Nashville.
So you guys keep doing
what you're doing
'cause you are killing it.
Now, up next...
Nothing like warm butter
and lobster.
FIERI: ...a Denver diner
upping their food game
and taking over the town.
Prime time.
A few years ago, I went
to this joint in Denver
where they turned
an old garage...
Hydraulic lifts,
the cars out the side.
FIERI: ...into a diner
serving classic comfort food
from across the country.
Skirt steak,
chimichurri butter up.
FIERI: Now, it might be
a mile high there,
but the food is really
as down-to-earth as you can get.
This is Steuben's Food Service.
I saw Steuben's on "Triple-D."
Mm.
The food looked fantastic,
nice big portions,
caught my eye.
They featured the lobster roll,
so good.
FIERI:
Lobster roll in Denver?
[ Record scratches ]
Not exactly
what I was expecting.
Turns out owner Josh Wolkon
comes by them naturally.
So I grew up in New England
and grew up
with the New England
lobster roll.
FIERI: And he's got
his kitchen crew firing up
this East Coast specialty
for the Rocky Mountain crowd.
Pop off the tail.
Pop off the claws.
-Break down the tail meat.
-Looks good.
Dice up the tail meat,
large chunk.
-Split the claws.
-Now...
Goes into a bowl, and then we
make the lobster roll dressing.
Holy bucket of mayonnaise,
Batman.
-Chopped onions, celery.
-Nice dice on that.
Yeah, lemon juice, paprika,
some salt, pepper,
and we just mix it up.
Seems like it should be
a two-bunner.
-Really?
-Nah, you want it overflowing.
I don't want to get it
on your hand, man.
Oh, that was off.
[ Laughs ]
Do I want a fork?
Do you guys think at home
I want a fork?
Absolutely not.
That's really good. Mm.
The fact that you guys are doing
this from fresh,
pretty impressive, man.
Nice job.
And this joint isn't just about
representing back east.
They're all about serving up
a mixed bag of
regional favorites.
I mean, the menu is pretty
eclectic, everything from,
you know, the lobster rolls
to Chicago dogs
to some crazy brined chicken.
So we're gonna truss
and brine some whole chickens
before we roast them.
Truss and brine, I like it.
Wings go back across the legs.
The more you keep this
all together,
the better it's gonna cook
and the more you're
gonna hold in the juices.
And then let's make the brine.
We get some brown sugar, salt,
some whole cloves,
whole black peppercorns.
Go for it, a little bay leaf.
-And then a grip of water.
-A grip?
It's about five gallons,
then whisk.
It goes over the birds.
These things are just gonna be
full of flavor.
So they're brined 24 hours,
give them a little shake dry.
In the oven about 40 minutes.
Look at that.
And right there, my friend,
prime time bird, man,
prime time.
Nashville hot fried chicken.
FIERI: Nowadays, the bird
has flown south
with their Nashville hot fried,
and they've gone international
with their French-inspired
Monte Cristo.
The Monte Cristo just really
hits everything
that Steuben's is.
It is classic comfort food.
You know you're being a little
bit naughty, but it's delicious.
Two slices of white bread,
one side you get
Swiss and the roasted ham.
On the other side,
American cheese, roasted turkey,
dipped in the egg mixture,
put it in the fryer,
just enough to get
that golden brown
and a little bit of that
crispiness, powdered sugar,
and then it's served with
a house-made raspberry preserve.
Monte Cristo, table 12.
Sweet exterior with the batter,
powdered sugar,
and then
the nice savory interior
with the meat and cheese,
and it's delicious.
And with this jelly,
and you dip it in,
and it's getting salty
and sweet and golden,
and it's so amazing.
FIERI: With so many stops around
Flavortown,
I just had one question.
Where's my California
representation, huh?
What's up with that?
A taco. I mean, come on.
Now, they didn't give me a taco,
but they did add chilaquiles
since I left.
We start with the roast chuck,
gets seasoned, oregano, parsley,
basil, garlic powder, and then
into the oven 20 minutes.
So while we're getting that
sear on there,
we're working on the mirepoix,
celery, onions,
carrots, bay leaf, thyme,
pour it all over the roast
with red wine and beef stock.
And then it goes back in for
three to four hours
on a slow cook,
and then we start to shred it.
And then we add the salsa roja.
We cook together,
and then we add the tortillas.
We add the eggs any way
you want them.
I like them over easy.
Then we garnish it with avocado,
cotija,
and a little green onion.
Order of chilaquiles for you.
I grew up in
Southern California.
Chilaquiles
reminds me of home.
The beef is really tender.
It's amazing.
Chilaquiles,
it's got some spice.
It's got great meat.
The egg on top, the avocado,
nice textured flavors.
So since the original Steuben's,
we opened up Steuben's Arvada
right here.
Now, we have
our two food trucks.
And your gravy fries.
We added breakfast when
we opened up here in Arvada.
Traffic jam, in the window!
We make our ice cream here.
And we're hopefully gonna be
out at the airport someday.
Gentlemen, I'll tell you,
funky joint, fun joint.
Everybody seems to be having
a good time
when they come to Steuben's.
-Absolutely.
-Save me a table. I'll be back.
-Right on.
-Okay? Thank you, brother.
-Thank you.
-Good times.
Opening at the airport?
Just what I like to hear,
going the extra mile in Denver.
Now, coming up...
I'm gonna get kicked out of
the culinary club on this one.
...a seafood joint in Miami
running a risk
with their lobster.
And spoiler alert, it ends up
paying off big-time.
When you get back after this
commercial, you get to see this.
♪♪
In Miami's Little Havana,
I found this funky family-run
Cuban joint
dishing out seafood like,
now wait for it, fried lobster.
And you had to eat on your feet.
Well, it's still
standing room only,
but that's just because
of the crowds.
This is the one
and only La Camaronera.
Been coming here
since I was about 10 years old,
and the same good food
since day one.
It's so wonderful now.
Now, you can actually sit down
and have a nice lunch.
It's always had the freshest
seafood in Miami.
That's why I keep coming back.
Minuta, table 11!
FIERI:
When I first met David Garcia,
he was just a young buck
serving up Cuban family recipes
alongside his dad and uncle,
the guys who started this place.
-[ Whistles ]
-Florida lobster here.
So where's the claws?
Florida lobsters do not have
the claws
like the Maine lobster.
-Seriously?
-Yeah.
We're gonna prepare
this lobster up.
What we do is,
we get the tail out.
We just split the tail in half.
Wow.
It's got a pinkish meat
versus the white
we see in the Maine.
Right.
So what's in the red sauce?
Lemon juice, salt, comino,
pepper, ground garlic.
It looks like we're gonna
add ketchup now.
I'll be over here.
Want to try it?
Wow. Wow. [ Laughs ]
He wet his feet.
I spilled ketchup on him.
I made him use
our concrete blender.
[ Blender whirring ]
We're digging deep down
into the base of the volcano.
He was just like one of us.
The warm water lobster,
the ketchup sauce.
The red sauce and some flour,
all-purpose.
-Yep.
-Dip this into the red sauce.
We're not really making a lot
of sense
right now here
in my culinary world,
but I am enjoying
where we're going.
Now, we're gonna do
something we've never done on
"Triple-D," fry lobster.
I'm gonna get kicked out of
the culinary club on this one.
You can tell that
he was caught off guard
with some of our methods.
But knowing that for 35 years
everybody was eating it
already here,
I knew he was gonna love it.
Nothing wrong with that. Ah.
Great texture,
really nice crunch.
-Wow.
-Tasty.
Yeah.
Okay, now the hot sauce.
That's pretty mild.
Not really. Get my water.
Wow.
Kind of comes in at the end
doesn't it?
[ Laughter ]
These days, they're putting
a new spin on this
tried and true favorite.
We decided to do
a lobster sandwich.
FIERI: The big difference --
the sauce
they're serving it with.
We're gonna make
our pink sauce here,
just a little bit spicy.
We start with a bowl of mayo.
We add a little bit of sriracha,
paprika, parsley, and water
to thin it out.
It's light.
It goes great with fried
lobster sandwich.
It's lightly breaded.
When you bite through it,
it's got a nice consistency.
The pink sauce has just
the right amount of sweetness
with a little bit of spice.
It's a really nice touch.
FIERI: That pink sauce
is also siding up
with their new shrimp empanadas.
This is fresh Gulf Coast shrimp,
chopped up.
We're gonna add
some granulated garlic,
a little cumin,
ground black pepper.
We have some soffritto of
green peppers, red peppers,
and onions,
add a little bit
of paprika here.
Stuff our empanadas,
about 2 ounces worth.
Flip it over.
Fold them up and cook them up
about four minutes.
The filling has a nice
little spice to it,
but not too spicy and not too
overpowering of the shrimp
that's inside the empanada.
Nice crust on the outside,
sweet shrimp
with a little bit of spice.
The sauce is fantastic.
So I know you guys ask me
all the time,
"Did you eat all of that?"
On this, I did eat
almost all of that.
♪♪
My dad and his brother
started it,
and now my cousin
and I are here.
It's a testament to
our fathers' hard work.
Here we are today.
Seriously, man. Nice job.
♪♪
That's awesome. Four more places
still going strong --
a seafood joint sticking with
the family tradition,
a grilled cheese mecca
in Nashville,
a Denver diner putting out
dishes from all over Flavortown,
plus a Fieri family secret
I'm sharing with the nation.
And that's just a drop
in the bucket,
ladies and gentlemen.
We got a long list
to get through next time
on "Triple-D Nation."
[ Whistling ]
Hey, hey! Thank you.
[ Laughter ]
-Be here all week.
-Really?