Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ho!
...we're digging into everything
from pretzels and pork...
This is next level.
...to prime‐time paella.
Gorgeous.
Like in Little Rock...
I'm in heaven.
...where things
are getting twisted...
Does somebody on the team
have octopus arms?
...along with
some international flair.
Look at that!
Plus farm‐to‐table in Montana...
Come to Bozeman,
that's outstanding.
...that's worth waking up to.
That's one of the best
breakfast dishes
I've had on "Triple D."
I mean, wow!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins
&amp; Dives."
♪♪♪♪
So I'm here in Bozeman, Montana,
right across the street
from Montana State University.
Now, we've all heard the term
"farm‐to‐table," right?
Well, I'm here to check
out a joint
where a husband and wife team ‐‐
well, they're taking it
to a whole nother level.
You see, because they own the
farm and they have the tables.
This is Storm Castle Cafe.
Grandma's enchilada, waffle,
please, in the window!
This is the best breakfast
in Bozeman.
I have
the Monte Cristo for you.
WOMAN: Thank you.
FIERI: This isn't your average
breakfast‐and‐lunch
kind of joint, this is
a little [whistles]
‐Yeah.
‐...over the top.
It's always packed in here.
Everyone's always here.
FIERI: Maybe because Bozeman
native Chef Scott Peterson
is serving up a spot
that feels like home.
This area's changed a lot
in the last 10 years.
Right.
And so, we just wanted
to create
an experience
that was an authentic
Montana experience
that you might have got
sometime in the past.
And while wife, Nicole, heads up
the front of the house,
her Mexican heritage mixes in
to the kitchen, as well.
I have the pocampo.
I think this is Scott's version
of the chimichanga.
I've never had anything
like it anywhere. It's great.
So our first thing
that we're gonna make
is gonna be our pocampo,
which starts out
with our homemade carnitas.
We use either pork loin
or pork shoulder depending
on what we have in‐house.
‐What you have available.
You want to dice it up
in some fairly large cubes.
It gives it an opportunity
to be more succulent.
‐Okay.
‐We get a pan with the bacon fat
that's already hot.
Season it with salt and pepper.
That's all gonna go
till it's tender?
Not till
it's fall‐apart tender
'cause we're gonna do
another braise on it after this.
‐Got it.
‐So we have cumin here...
Okay.
...granulated garlic,
dried cilantro...
Chili powder.
...oregano that's dried,
a touch of cinnamon.
‐A little paprika.
‐This is paprika, for color.
Now, this is where it gets
interesting ‐‐
orange juice and milk?
‐Yeah.
There's some lactic acids
in the milk
that are gonna help break
down our pork a little bit,
and then it's gonna be
the citric acids
as well that are gonna
offer up a bit of sweetness.
How long's
this gonna cook?
It takes another 45 minutes
to an hour.
Next up?
We call it a fire‐roasted
salsa here,
but we're actually doing it
on the flat top.
Okay.
Green onions that we're
gonna char off, jalapeños,
fire‐roasted tomatoes,
onions.
‐Garlic go down?
‐Yeah. Garlic goes here.
As soon as they're charred,
we hit them in the pot,
we let that simmer until
the veggies are broken down.
And then just when
they're finished?
A little salt.
‐Yeah, and cilantro.
Immersion blender.
Next up is our queso.
Queso, you gonna
make it or not?
Yeah.
'Kay, so
you gonna make it?
So we start off with
a little bit of bacon fat.
For some reason, it seems
like you have bacon fat
running in your veins.
‐It's a pretty common theme.
We're gonna add
our flour to it
to create a little bit
of a roux.
This is our pico de gallo
that we make in‐house.
We're gonna add
a little bit of beer.
‐Come on!
‐So we're gonna let
this simmer
so it starts to come out.
Add a little bit
of our milk.
So what we got here is
the cheese that melts.
Yeah!
And a little American?
A little bit of American,
just for body.
Just give it a whisk,
let it melt until it's smooth.
Done.
‐Okay.
Make it happen, Cap'n.
We're just gonna egg‐wash
this whole tortilla.
Jack cheese,
cheddar blend.
And then we have some potatoes,
season them,
sear them off
with peppers, onions.
Those are dynamite!
And then our carnitas
pork mixture.
Fold it over.
We roll it tight.
And then after we get
to this point...
‐Fry them for service?
‐Correct.
Let's put it together, man.
I'm hungry.
Here's what we do now
to finish this.
These are our signature
cowboy beans, we call them.
Pinto beans cooked off
with a lot of bacon fat,
onions, jalapeños.
A little bit
of cotija cheese.
People like that breakfast
for dinner.
This is a meal.
This is ‐‐ I mean,
it's outstanding.
All that delicious pork.
Not over‐fried,
not greasy.
♪♪♪♪
Wow!
Those beans
are banging, dude.
Thank you.
You're putting more attention
and detail
to a breakfast item
than most people put
into a dinner item.
I don't care where anybody
is right now,
if you're within
200 miles of Bozeman,
I'd make a pilgrimage
for this.
I will come back
That's one of the best
breakfast dishes
I've had on "Triple D."
Thank you very much.
One of the best,
without question. Wow!
‐Pocampo for you.
‐Thank you.
The beans, the cheese sauce,
the pork,
Scott knows
how to pull it all together.
Picking up!
Storm Castle Burger.
The whole farm‐to‐table aspect
comes together so well.
FIERI:
'Cause much of the ingredients
are coming from the farm
Scott and his parents have run
since the 1970s.
We raise the majority
of the pork.
‐Okay.
‐We have a herd of red Angus.
We have a garden ‐‐
zucchini,
cucumbers, squash,
all that kind of stuff.
But occasionally, his
do‐it‐yourself attitude leads
to should‐have‐paid‐someone‐
else‐to‐do‐it results.
I farrow pigs, right,
which means that these sows
are gonna have babies.
‐Right.
So 250, 300 covers yesterday,
working on the line,
I find out
I'm having pigs.
I cruise out to the farm,
we deliver 16 pigs.
I get done at 10:00
last night,
when I decided
to cut my hair.
Except, you see this
little streak right here?
That's where I missed.
‐You cut yourself?!
Cut myself with a pair
of clippers
at 10:30 last night.
‐You're an animal.
I thought you were running
a faux‐hawk.
I like it.
‐We're picking up a chili
and a biscuit, Monte,
and a pocampo.
What else you got up
your sleeve?
I believe we're gonna ‐‐
Well, hang on, hang on,
let's not even do this.
I'm gonna try
to finish this plate.
Here's the deal, I'm hanging out
in Bozeman, Montana,
you are going
to love this place.
When we come back, we're gonna
make something else.
Good food's
just good food.
See you in a bit.
♪♪♪♪
Welcome back, we're hanging out
at Storm Castle Cafe
in Bozeman, Montana.
I'm gonna tell you, bro.
I haven't been to Bozeman,
Montana, before,
but if this is what
the food scene is like,
I'm gonna be back for more.
Poncho, pick up!
MAN: As much of the products
as they can,
they raise
on their own farm,
so it's gonna be
as fresh as possible.
WOMAN #2:
They do breakfast and lunch,
we would love for them
to do dinner.
Maybe someday.
So what are we gonna make?
‐To be honest,
what we called it was,
"Our Farm" in the beginning.
Most of the products
come from our farm.
‐Our Farm didn't sell.
‐Didn't sell.
My wife's printing
the menu up,
why don't we just
change the name ‐‐
Monte Cristo.
‐Now it sells out the door.
Alright, I've got
the Monte Cristo.
The perfect combination
of sweet and savory.
You've really got quite a meal
here. It's great.
It's not quite a classic
Monte Cristo,
we don't serve it with jam,
we serve it
with a strawberry‐rhubarb syrup
or a seasonal syrup.
We put them in a pot.
Sugar, vanilla...
‐So your standard compote.
‐Yeah.
...and maple syrup.
Cooks down,
we're gonna puree this?
Yeah.
And this is the beginning
of the Monte Cristo?
This is the beginning.
What we do to it
that's a little bit different,
is that we make
a French toast batter.
We take our eggs, sugar,
we get that
mixed up real good,
then we're gonna add
our vanilla,
not a lot of milk
to be honest.
‐Got it.
‐It's just a light dunk.
‐Boom, boom.
‐And then we let it crisp up.
And then as it cools down,
that sugar that was caramelized
on the outside crunches
like a crème brûlée.
Then we're gonna add
our Swiss cheese.
This is your ham?
It is.
Mm.
Put it together,
let it cool.
Hit it in the batter,
drop it in the fryer.
Wow!
I've seen a lot
of Monte Cristos.
We're gonna cut into it.
Ho!
♪♪♪♪
This is our
strawberry‐rhubarb syrup
that we made earlier.
Then we open
that sandwich up.
‐Whoa!
‐Cheese.
Oh, my kids picked the wrong day
to miss this show.
Then we're gonna hit it
with powdered sugar.
‐Of course you are.
‐Yep.
That's ridiculous.
Gonna have
to hunch this.
Mm.
"Dear
Webster's Dictionary,
I have a new picture
for your definition
of the Monte Cristo."
Monte Cristos are great.
This is next level.
The work of hitting that
brûléed French toast...
...the delicious ham...
...the
strawberry rhubarb ‐‐
that syrup, that tang
just counterbalances
everything.
So, one minute, you're getting
the sweet and the crunch,
the next you're getting
the salt and the cheese
and the ham and the tang.
I mean, wow!
This is
a destination dish.
I don't know where
you're planning on going.
Oh, Europe?
No, stop.
Come back over here.
Come to Bozeman.
That's outstanding.
I've got the Monte Cristo.
It just has a very kind
of smoky flavor,
so it goes well
with the sweet.
It's the best.
It's yummy goodness.
Picking up, please!
Poncho.
Trout.
MAN: When you come through
Bozeman, make sure you stop in.
It's great food.
Brother,
it's all about you
and what you guys
do here.
This is remarkable.
‐Thank you.
‐Excellent job.
‐Thank you, man.
I'll be back.
FIERI: Up next, a funky brew pub
in Little Rock...
That works for sure.
...getting saucy
with the menu...
That gumbo gets it.
...giving new life
to old favorites.
That's how
you get it done.
Dude, I don't even know
who you remind me of.
You remind me of
some of my buddies.
When's your birthday?
‐Wednesday.
[ Laughter ]
So, I'm here in North
Little Rock, Arkansas,
just about a half mile
from the downtown area
to check out a joint.
Well, it's these two buddies
that met in college.
One was a stay‐at‐home dad
and the other became
a high school teacher,
and they decided,
"Hey, let's open up
a brewery and serve pretzels."
Well, then they met
this chef that said,
"Let's expand the menu."
And the story just
goes on from there.
This is Flyway Brewing Company.
Serving this Cheddar Bomber!
Rocking every day, all day!
The menu here is very unique.
JONES: Serving up
fried green tomatoes!
WOMAN #3:
They put flavors together
that other people
don't think about.
‐And it works.
‐How long on them venisons?
It's your go‐to brewery
when you come to town.
FIERI: That's because
co‐owners Matt Foster
and Jesse McMullan
know their beers.
FIERI: How many different
beers you guys making?
Over 50 year‐round.
And you make the root beer
as well?
Yeah.
Don't want to get
those kegs mixed up.
Yeah, exactly right.
And the food to go
with their brew, they tapped
Chef Gina Jones
to spice up their menu.
We were looking for someone
that maybe could bring in some
Southern food that could mix
with some soul foods
and some Cajun
and some Creole.
FIERI: But first, she needed
to master the O. G. recipe
the boys first paired up
with their pints.
Here is the pretzel tree.
They give you a good amount
of options
with the different salts
and sauces you can have.
It's almost like ordering
10 different meals in one.
Alright, so what are we
gonna make first, Chef?
We're gonna make
the pretzel.
Just so you know,
I used to sell pretzels
when I was a little kid.
I had the awesome
pretzel cart.
I'm a pretzel junkie.
We'll pour all‐purpose flour.
Get it all in there.
Don't you think they
would have come up
with an easier way
to get the flour in?
I know.
We all dump it right there
on the side.
Keep going.
You got it.
Okay.
Salt, sugar, yeast.
So, we mix all the dry
ingredients first.
And then slowly put
your water in there.
And how many pretzels are you
guys making in a week?
Anywhere from 600
to 700 pretzels a week.
Does somebody on the team
have octopus arms?
Now my butter.
It's gonna take us
about a good 30 minutes
to get it all
mixed together.
Then we let it rest
for how long?
An hour or so.
Roll it out.
Wrap it around.
And we make one type
of pretzel dough,
but we do a lot
of different sauces
and a lot of different salts.
‐Yes.
Alright, we're gonna go
to a water bath
with a little baking soda.
‐Yes, sir.
We'll cook them
for about 15 minutes.
While those are cooking,
we're making sauces.
We're first gonna make
our hickory mustard.
Mustard, ketchup,
brown sugar,
"watch your sister" ‐‐
Worcestershire...
"Watch your sister"
sauce.
...apple cider,
chili powder, garlic powder.
‐Okay.
‐Liquid smoke goes on there.
This will cook for like
10 minutes.
Next one we're making is, what?
The honey mustard?
Yes, sir, and this goes
with our Migrate pretzel.
"Migraine"?
Not "migraine"
like a headache.
"Migrate" like a bird.
‐Okay, Migrate pretzel.
‐Yes.
Got it.
‐So you got mustard here...
‐With the mayonnaise.
...apple cider again,
garlic powder,
put salt in there,
the honey that make it
sweet and delicious.
And that one we don't
have to cook.
Just stir and go.
FIERI: That's
a nice‐looking pretzel.
We butter them up.
Boy, you look nice,
pretzel.
Oh, a different
buttering up.
And then this is gonna be
the which one?
This is the Free Range.
This is
the bacon salt here.
So, you grind up bacon
with salt?
Yes.
This goes with
the hickory mustard.
My favorite.
So, you get the bacon
of the pretzel,
and then you get the smoke
from the liquid smoke,
so it's like
a smoky mustard sauce.
‐Mm‐hmm.
‐That works for sure.
Mm. Alright,
what's the next one?
Migrate.
This is lavender salt.
This comes with
our honey mustard.
I'm in heaven.
Much more on
the traditional style.
Both of them are screaming,
"Drink more beer."
I think that's kind
of the idea.
But I do have to say
that the bacon salt
with the hickory sauce ‐‐
I think that's going
to be my favorite.
But why don't we try
all the rest of them, too,
just so I can be sure.
We can do that.
I like the way you roll.
Migrate pretzel.
Having the different,
unique flavors ‐‐
it's excellent.
It's hot. It comes out fresh,
and you can really taste that.
‐Have you always been a cook?
‐No.
Someone say, "Well,
you enjoy cooking,
but you would have to go
to Kentucky to go to school."
And I was like,
"I'm here in Arkansas."
And sure enough, they finally
opened up a school
for us here in Arkansas.
So, how long did you go
to culinary school?
I went to school
for 2 years,
and I'm going back
to get my bachelor's.
That's how
you get it done.
MAN #2: She changed what
they were offering.
She elevated it and brought it
to a new level.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
‐Gumbo fries.
‐Gumbo cheese fries.
Her gumbo is as good as anything
I've had in New Orleans.
WOMAN #4: And it's all with
this big steak fry.
It really soaks up the juices.
‐What makes good gumbo?
‐Me.
"Me."
Let's see it.
JONES: So, this is how I start
my roux ‐‐ oil and flour.
This takes anywhere from,
like, 20 to 30 minutes.
Okay, so roux
goes in the back.
Put my veggies in,
then the garlic, my sausage.
‐Andouille.
‐Take my roux...
Nice and dark.
...pour it over in there,
chicken stock.
‐Chili flake.
‐Greek seasoning.
‐Shrimp?
‐Yes, sir.
Crawfish?
Yes.
Chicken.
‐A little hot sauce.
Fries are done.
Cajun salt there.
Cheese.
Put them in the oven
for about two minutes.
Then the gumbo
goes on top?
‐Yes, sir.
‐Got it.
Scallions going on here
for garnish
with our house
ranch dressing.
Alright, alright.
Mmm.
That gumbo gets it.
Great rich flavor,
not too spicy,
all the right
ingredients ‐‐
crawfish, shrimp,
the andouille.
But the key was all the love
in that roux ‐‐
nice and dark and rich.
Thank you, Chef.
Nicely done.
Here are the gumbo fries.
WOMAN #5: The amount of cheese,
the amount of the sauce ‐‐
it just really melts
in your mouth.
It's comfort food.
I love it.
JONES: Nashville Hot Bites!
How'd you guys
find the Flyway?
Everybody knows
about the Flyway.
You're either new
or dumb.
If you're new, you know
quickly about Flyway.
If you're dumb...
If you're dumb,
that's your problem.
You'll figure it out soon.
Okay.
It's just my favorite place,
absolutely.
Boy, these folks sure struck
a gold mine when they got you.
Thank you, Chef.
Come on now.
Nice job.
‐Thank you.
♪♪♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, we're sticking
to Little Rock...
Beautiful.
...but it feels like
Venezuela...
Guests that come in here
must go nuts for this.
...with a hearty Spanish spin.
I'm warming up for it.
♪♪♪♪
You know, a lot of people
don't know this,
but I was an exchange student in
France when I was 16 years old.
Amazing experience.
And I'm here in Little Rock,
Arkansas,
where I hear
there's a restaurant owner
that has a similar story,
except he was an exchange
student from Venezuela.
I hear the story is awesome,
and the food's even better.
This is La Terraza.
♪♪♪♪
[ Speaks Spanish ]
It's just a fantastic place.
It's very amazing to have
a Venezuela restaurant in town.
Slicing the pernil.
‐You're from Venezuela?
‐Yeah.
You came to the United States
as an exchange student?
Right.
Then you went to go
to the university.
That's when Armando Bolaños
met his wife, Sara.
You excited to try
something new today?
Then you bring your parents
from Venezuela?
Yep.
Who brought with them experience
owning a Spanish tapas
restaurant.
So, it was a perfect recipe
to all partner up on this place.
What's the food?
‐A little Spanish influence,
really, a little bit
of French and Italian.
And then I see Venezuelan
on the menu.
Pernil Al Horno
there for you, my dear.
Pernil's awesome ‐‐
really simple
but really flavorful
at the same time.
And the beans and rice that come
with it feel like
they've been cooking
on somebody's stove for days.
Pernil Al Horno ‐‐
pork leg, oven bake.
Alright, well,
let's get into it.
We're gonna start
by peeling the skin back.
And this is your
traditional Venezuelan?
The pernil is.
It's a dish that everybody
has a spin of.
We're gonna make
the liquid ‐‐
mix mustard, white wine,
Worcestershire, and salt.
‐And this is for the injection?
‐Yeah.
We're gonna puncture holes
in the pork...
Alright,
Freddy Krueger.
...and we're
gonna stuff it.
So the rest of
the injection liquid ‐‐
red and green bell peppers,
some onions.
We stuff
this whole thing...
And then we put
the rosemary, too.
Well, this isn't going
to be lacking flavor,
I'll tell you that much.
Salt?
‐Yeah.
...wrap the skin
back over...
Pour the leftover
liquid mix.
‐Worcestershire.
‐White wine.
And a little ‐‐
what kind of stock?
Chicken.
Wrap it up in the oven.
What temp?
350.
6 to 8 hours.
Alright, Chef.
We're gonna serve it
with congri rice.
Let's see it.
‐Bacon, onions, black beans.
Going to need a little
pre‐cooked rice.
Oh, I'm ready for that.
Bacon, onion,
beans, and rice?
That's my middle name.
Hey, is at that Guy Bacon Onion
Beans and Rice Fieri?
Sure is.
Alright, Chef.
Are we ready?
‐Yes, sir.
Let's see it.
Look at that.
Slice it thin.
What's ‐‐ we're making a sauce?
Going to let this heat
up a little bit.
Demiglace, the drippings
from the braised ham leg,
and chicken stock?
Yeah.
The congri...
The congri.
You're gonna break
somebody's plate.
There's gonna be
a lot of trouble.
It's happened before.
I bet
it's happened before,
and then I'm gonna tell
your mom and dad.
‐Tostones.
‐Fried plantains.
And then we'll add the pork,
parsley...
It's the magic.
♪♪♪♪
What do you think?
So good.
When you take that delicious,
tender pork,
slow‐cook it
with all that flavor,
and inject it in a bunch
of the reduced
demiglace gravy,
the guests that come in here
must go nuts for this.
Little scoop of the rice,
bacon, onion,
beans, and rice.
It's great.
♪♪ Bacon, onions, beans,
and rice ♪♪
It's my other song.
I have "Chicken, Basil,
Garlic Salt,"
and then I also have "Bacon,
Onions, Beans, and Rice"
It's on the same album ‐‐
you probably heard it.
Pernil up!
Delicious. The meat
is so tender.
WOMAN #6: The rice and beans
are fantastic.
I love the fried plantains.
I think it's a great dish.
How hungry are we?
Just a really nice atmosphere
they have created here.
It's called La Terraza because,
you know,
there's a beautiful,
fantastic terrace outside.
It's like
you're in a treehouse.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
It's authentic, so they're
gonna take their time,
everything's made
to order and fresh.
FIERI: Which is a must
for this Spanish classic.
We have our Valencian‐style
paella.
How beautiful is that?
Just a gorgeous dish.
Mussels, shrimp,
clams, chicken.
‐Chicken in the paella?
‐Chicken in the paella, yes.
‐Okay.
‐So we call it Valencian paella.
It's Valencian paella
'cause the chicken's
in the paella.
We start off with...
Garlic and olive oil,
bay leaves, onions,
cured chorizo,
red and green peppers.
And your parents were the ones
that taught you
how to make this?
‐Yeah.
We're ready
for the chicken.
Cook it
for a little bit...
Got you.
...then the calamari next,
the shrimp.
Now we'll do the rice.
‐Hard‐boiled rice?
‐Hard‐boiled rice.
‐I'm warming up for it.
Chicken stock ‐‐
no seafood stock.
Correct.
A little salt.
‐A little Sazón.
‐Sazón, uh‐huh.
A little annatto seed in there
for that great color.
Mm‐hmm.
We'll add the clams
and the mussels, red peppers,
and some peas...
‐Just to finish it off.
Cover really tight.
So now that just simmers?
‐35 minutes.
‐Gorgeous!
Olive oil,
and then sherry wine.
Beautiful.
And you'll plate this
right at the table for them?
Yes.
♪♪♪♪
Dude, we get a ton
of seafood flavor
with those mussels and shrimp,
the clams are nice.
That calamari is super,
super tender.
I love the bay leaf in it ‐‐
a touch of that ‐‐
the acidity from the sherry,
all plays in really well.
But most importantly,
that flavor of that seafood
in that paella ‐‐
spot on.
Dress this up with a little bit
of sherry and olive oil here.
It's just really beautiful
and feels really authentic.
It's really great.
I'm definitely gonna come
back and have it again.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
It's just a great place to be.
Because it's an experience
that you've never, ever had.
‐Well done, man.
‐Thank you.
Well done.
You're doing good for yourself.
Exchange student kid
from Venezuela
comes to the United States ‐‐
live the American dream, man.
‐Yeah.
‐Proud of you.
Thank you.
So that's it for this road trip,
but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive‐ins, &amp; Dives."
‐Cooking duck.
Duck on a stick.
Duck in a pot.
‐Fried duck.
‐Boiled duck.
‐Sandwich.
Boiled duck.
‐Grilled duck.
‐Duck stew.
‐Smoked duck.
Dock confit.