I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're going round two,
revisiting some of our favorite
diners, drive-ins and dives.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous,
dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning...
[ Both laugh ]
...'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up...
Did you see that?!
...and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
an oyster-shucking shack...
Ah! Yeah!
...putting a new spin on
and old New-Orleans favorite...
Those are delicious.
Tip your waitress,
and try the oysters.
...a joint
in Northern California
lifted a page out
of Nonnie's cookbook...
You put that in a flip-flop,
that would taste good.
...and in Phoenix, Arizona,
a chef going gangster...
Meet my "sista"
from another "mista."
...taking Flavortown
south of the border.
That's Mayan flavors
right there.
They're my flavors now.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah!
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So, I'm here in New Orleans,
about three miles
from the French Quarter,
and you know that old saying,
"Time flies when
you're having fun"?
Well, man, has time flew,
and, boy, am I having fun.
I'm here to check out a joint
I haven't seen in 10 years.
Now, I must've sent hundreds
of thousands of people
to check this place out.
All right.
Oyster loaf ready.
FIERI: We're talking
real-deal family,
a good history,
and oysters that are
off the hook.
This is Casamento's.
Chargrilled oysters.
Our quintessential
New Orleans hot spot.
I saw Casamento's
on "Triple D,"
and it was really great.
Of course, I've known it
much before they did.
FIERI: And no, this isn't
a place I can visit just once,
'cause this local landmark
is hitting 100 --
open since 1919,
when original owner,
Joe Casamento,
shucked his first oyster here.
-How you doing, man?
-How you been, man?
And third-generation owner,
C.J. Gerdes,
is still shucking them
like Grandpa did.
GERDES: I've been shucking
since I was 14.
My grandfather didn't
give me a choice.
You're still
running the show.
-Yeah.
-You didn't age.
Do we look any different...
from 10 years ago?
Big bear.
Some things never change,
and C.J.'s still banging out
some of the biggest, baddest
oysters in the Big Easy.
Who was the guy that was
shucking with us that day?
That was
his brother.
-It was your brother.
-Yeah.
Are you
as fast as him?
FIERI: Now, that would
be saying something.
-He's number-one.
GERDES:
He's number-one.
His bro, Mike Rogers,
was the fastest shucker
in the bayou.
I want you
to try this at home.
Wanna keep your hands and feet
inside the ride at all times.
Go.
Okay, that was the first one
in six seconds.
Two in 12 seconds.
That's eight.
And this is will round out 10
in 1:05.
And you need
more people?
Do you put it up
against this thing?
The first couple of them
looked like
they went through a blender.
[ Imitates blender ]
Right.
After that,
he did pretty good.
FIERI: You can see
the evolution.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
All right,
so tell me what's new.
That's a new dish we have --
chargrilled oysters.
It was invented here
in New Orleans years ago.
GERDES: It starts
with butter,
minced garlic,
parsley flake,
some Cajun seasoning,
Worcestershire sauce.
The last is lemon.
Now my sauce gets taken back
to the chargrill area.
The oyster sits
on a half-shell.
Then you add all
the Parmesan cheese on.
Pour the sauce on it, and
the cheese melts all over it.
And it'll cook
inside the shell.
We make the oyster cook
about half to three-quarter way.
♪♪
That's a lot of cheese.
What's the cheese?
GERDES:
It's Parmesan.
-Fresh-grated?
-Fresh-grated.
Must be.
They're fresh.
Those are delicious.
SERVER:
Chargrilled oysters.
The Parmesan crust
is just so good.
And the butter, you just
lap it up with the bread.
And you keep going back
for more.
Getting these off the grill
with the Parmesan cheese
and the garlic
and lemon juice,
it can't get any better
than this.
How many oysters you guys
going through these days?
Phew.
In a busy day,
we'll go through about 80 sacks.
You were at 50 a day.
-Yeah.
-You went up to 80 a day.
-80 a day.
-I love it.
♪♪
I'ma need you
to stand over there.
FIERI: Ready?
Oh!
You remember that?
I remember the first one
hit you in the eye.
He got it on the second
or the third take,
right in his mouth.
Yeah!
I'll be performing
here all week.
Tip your waitress,
and try the oysters.
FIERI: You don't change
a lot of the menu.
I mean, the menu stayed the same
way for quite a while, right?
Yeah, everything's
still on the menu.
Soft shell crab sandwich,
oyster loaf.
-Oyster loaf?
-Mm-hmm.
Put them in my corn flour
and my salt.
Just drop them in,
and a bunch of them.
We have this thing called
deep-fat fryers.
-Mm-hmm.
-Okay.
You are still frying everything
the same way.
-Definitely.
-No fryer.
No fryer.
You old-schooled this
from the beginning,
and you haven't changed.
-That's right.
If it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
This is the breads we use,
right here.
I don't know that I have seen
a loaf of bread not sliced.
And I don't know
that on "Triple D"
I've seen
anybody whip out
the holiday carving knife,
either.
Still cutting my bread with the
electric carving knife, yeah.
I feel that Philly hunch
coming in.
I mean,
a little privacy?
Mmm, that's good.
Boy, that's fresh-tasting.
I like the way
you roll...
and the way you loaf.
FIERI: And now he's loaf-ing
all kind of seafood,
including shrimp.
GERDES: I know
you're gonna do your hunch.
I don't know if I can even
get after that.
That's a little bit bigger
than my head.
I'm gonna take
a petite bite.
Really good.
It's awesome, man.
What else?
That's fried crab claws,
and they sell a lot.
We take our crab claws,
dump them in the egg wash.
That's egg and milk.
You're gonna dip it
into corn flour.
No deep fryers.
That's why everything comes out
golden-brown all the time.
Food that comes out
looking like that --
that's what it's all about.
Do you eat
the whole thing?
Pull the meat
right off the bone.
Dynamite.
-Crab claws.
-Thank ya.
They really are so light.
I just wanted
to keep eating them.
Mixing them with the horseradish
and the ketchup
and dipping them --
so good.
Mmm.
[ Accent ] You can try
the oyster blender.
It's fantastic here.
[ Normal voice ]
What you see is what you get.
-Wait in line.
-That's it.
-Let's go shuck some oysters.
-Yep.
Pick up the oyster loaf
for table three.
Business pick up, though,
after the show?
Business went
through the roof.
It got crazy in here.
Fried shrimp coming out.
Still closed
in the summer?
in the summer.
I gotta have playtime.
[ Chuckles ]
Dude!
Get somebody else
to run the show!
-Love it.
-Yeah.
Listen, C.J.
If you're throwing a 100-year
anniversary celebration,
make sure I get an invitation,
all right?
That would be one heck
of a party.
Coming up,
in Northern California,
another multi-generation joint
pulling recipes
from Nonnie and Nonno.
Perfection
is what this is.
And this one, I gotta
take a little credit for.
Your dad still owes me
for giving you that job.
FIERI: I while ago,
I went over to Geyserville --
a small little wine-country town
in Northern California,
not too far from my hometown --
to check out this place.
But it's not just any place,
because I actually hired
the owner years ago
in one of my restaurants.
Now, I can only imagine
how a coach feels
when one of his players
turns pro,
'cause that's the feeling I have
when one of my guys ventures out
to open his own place.
It's a family-run joint
that's spanned generations,
and is still going strong.
This is Catelli's.
44, sausage clam.
Everybody here
is so friendly.
The staff is so welcoming.
And the food --
it's never disappointing.
Knowing that Nick,
Domenica, and Guy
have known each other
for years --
Guy's part
of the Catelli family.
FIERI: You could consider me
a distant cousin
to Nick and Domenica Catelli...
Spaghetti DC sauce!
...the third-generation
brother-and-sister team
running the family biz.
My nonnie and nonno,
Virginia and Santi,
opened Catelli's in 1935.
How does it feel?
Uh, surreal.
NICK: You're walking
in your grandparents'
and your father's footsteps
through this whole building.
FIERI: But his baby steps
started out in a placed
I know a little something about.
Here you go.
Didn't know that one
of the greatest things
I would get a chance to see is
somebody that came
from my restaurant
move on to do
his own restaurant.
NICK: Started
as a dishwasher and a busboy,
and then ended up working
for the company
for 13-1/2 years
in every position.
Your dad still owes me
for giving you that job.
That's Nick's dad,
right there.
You owe me, like,
12 Father's Day cards, Rich.
We've known Guy since
before he was "Guy" --
20-plus years.
-That's a del.
-Wow.
-You been working out?
-Yes, I have.
Just on that arm,
though.
[ Chuckles ]
When we were first
on "Diners,"
Guy featured
our meatball sliders.
DOMENICA: Organic beef
and our house-made sausage.
-Okay.
-Ricotta cheese.
This is my mix of panko
and Gruyère cheese.
Onion.
Garlic.
This one's Parm.
-Parsley?
-Italian parsley.
An egg in there.
-Mix all this together.
-Bake them first?
No, we do them
in a cast-iron skillet.
Hang on a second.
We cook them raw
to order.
You cook them raw to order
for every one
that goes
to the dining room?
Yes.
You are crazy.
I'm coming back
after this airs,
see if you're still
cooking these from raw.
As business has grown,
we've needed to find
how we can streamline.
And what we've found is
by throwing them
in the fryer quickly,
they take a lot less time.
FIERI: But was hasn't changed is
how she makes her DC red sauce.
"DC," you get it?
Domenica Catelli!
Extra-virgin olive oil, garlic,
hot pepper flakes.
Organic tomatoes.
-California?
-Yes.
-And just a little bit of salt?
Yep.
How long will you
just let this cook?
-For about an hour.
-Love it.
They go on the buns
and then we're gonna
pour the sauce over them
and cheese them up
with a little bit of parsley.
-Nice.
-Tell me what you think.
Delicious meatball.
It melts in your mouth
when you eat it.
No arguments here.
-Great job.
-Thank you.
FIERI: And these days,
Domenica's spicing up
some new dishes
with the same
righteous red sauced.
Clam, calamari,
and sausage sauté.
First, I'm going to add
our house-made sausage.
And then as that starts
to cook and get brown,
add our local clams,
a little bit of white wine,
and tomato sauce.
Let that cook
for a few minutes.
Then I'm gonna add
our fresh
Monterey-baked calamari.
It's just a perfect poor-man's
Chapino, I would say.
You got the clam, the calamari,
the sausage,
all in the red sauce.
-This is authentic.
-It is fantastic.
Everything is to perfection.
What are we gonna make?
We are making
the rav filling.
Pork butt.
Big beef chunks.
-Chicken.
-Skin-on.
And then, here's
our house-made sausage.
And we're gonna
roast this.
Going at 450
for how long?
30 to 40 minutes.
-We have to mix all our veg.
-Okay.
Onion, celery, garlic,
extra virgin olive oil,
Swiss chard.
Look at this --
such great texture,
great flavor.
Salt and pepper, yep.
And then
that's gonna go in.
-Into the oven?
-For about 40 minutes.
-All right.
-You're gonna dump the meat...
-And the juices.
-...into there.
Oh, it smells awesome.
So, the bread
gets mixed in.
Let's get all the veg
in there.
Now we're gonna put
the Pecorino and Parmesan.
Then we're gonna go
to the grinder.
Yes.
Now, I can't hold this
and be over there
eating any of that
at the same time.
-That's part of the plan.
-Look at that.
And you can taste it
at this point.
Mmm!
You put that in a flip-flop,
that would taste good.
We're making the dough
for the ravioli --
simple
Italian-style dough.
Some people add stuff in.
We don't.
-Okay.
-It's eggs and flour.
And the cool thing is,
is Ben Franklin lets you
use his mixer!
What?
FIERI: And that's not
the only thing
old-school around here.
This thing's gonna
hurt somebody.
We're following all
of Nonnie's kitchen rules...
-Can you read it?
-That's nuts.
...when we come back.
It's like an "Oprah"
episode.
My goodness.
I'm not giving away any
free cars, though.
So, I'm in Geyserville --
Northern California
wine-country --
to check out a place that
I've got some history with.
You see, Nick Catelli
worked his way up the ranks
in my NorCal restaurant...
Can I get you anything else?
FIERI: ...then reopened
his family's place
with his sister, Domenica.
To see what's happening
for the two of you,
as my friends
and working together,
and knowing how hard
you worked as a chef --
it chokes me up.
It's like an "Oprah"
episode.
My goodness.
I'm not giving away
any free cars, though.
FIERI: Catelli's has been
in the family since 1935,
and, apparently,
so has the kitchen equipment.
The Smithsonian called.
They want their first grinder
ever made back.
And the cool thing is,
is Ben Franklin lets you
use his mixer!
What?
But it's their take
on the recipes
Nonnie and Nonno Catelli
passed down
that make this place
bona fide Italian,
like their scratch-made ravioli.
So, this is gonna
be around one.
Crank it down
and just keep going.
How many times is this
gonna go through?
Eleven.
You got 27 hours
in a day here?
Okay, we're going
down to one,
and this is when we're
gonna read the newspaper.
-Can you read it?
-That's nuts.
So, the meat filling.
Put it into a pastry bag,
and go like that.
This is like therapy.
I feel good
about me.
Lay this on top,
press down,
and we're gonna
make our little squares,
so then you can
make it pretty.
What fantastic-ness
are you tossing that in?
Butter, garlic,
salt, parsley,
and a pinch
of Parmesan cheese.
Mangia.
It's so tender.
Perfection
is what this is.
This is one of the best raviolis
I've ever had.
Thank you.
And now she's back
in those noodles
in a brand-new way.
Our lasagna's a traditional
Italian style,
which is really thin
layers of pasta
with thin layers
of sauce in-between.
DOMENICA:
The cheese filling consists
of sheep's milk ricotta,
and we also use
whole-milk cow's ricotta.
Egg yolks, goat cheese,
fresh-ground pepper,
and kosher salt.
Parmesan, mint.
Finish that with some nutmeg.
Give this a final mix,
and then I'm gonna start
layering the pasta.
My red sauce,
and then we'll do a layer
with cheese and Parmesan
and another layer of pasta.
And then we're just gonna
keep building on top of that
until we get to the top.
We bake our lasagna off
at 350 degrees
for about 35 minutes.
♪♪
Got lasagna with
Domenica's sauce.
WOMAN: Thank you.
It's very light.
Pasta is so thin,
nice little bit of cheese --
I love it.
MAN: Buttery,
melts in your mouth --
it's hard to beat.
[ Bell dings ]
FIERI: You're doing
your family right.
You're doing the community
right.
You came back to Geyserville,
reopened Catelli's,
and that's so much more
than just the food.
It's the family.
It's the fun.
It's the experience.
It's the emotion.
It's the memories.
Guys, give it up
for the Catellis.
♪♪
-Huh?
-I love it.
Domenica and Nick
are crushing it!
Now, coming up, a Mexican place
in Phoenix, Arizona...
[ Speaking Spanish ]
[ Laughter ]
...time-travelling centuries
to bring Mayan flavor
to the masses.
Mmm.
In other words, it's good?
It's ridiculous!
♪♪
FIERI: Now, you know
that I love Mexican food.
I think you see that
on "Triple D" enough.
And in Phoenix, you can find
some of the best.
But this one, without question,
was as real-deal
as we've ever seen.
Let's go!
Let's get this out of here!
Listen, you won't find
chips and salsa here.
In fact, you might get thrown
out for even asking for them.
This is Barrio Cafe.
♪♪
I got a cochinita pibil
coming up.
Let's go!
MAN: When I saw it
on "Triple D,"
it turned out to be more than
I thought it would --
probably one of the best --
the best.
That's why I keep
on coming here.
WOMAN: You can tell
that these are traditional,
regional flavors.
And I'm so glad
that the Barrio Cafe is here.
FIERI: And it's all thanks
to Chef Silvana Salcido Esparza,
who's as real-deal
as the food she's rolling out.
I dig these shades,
by the way.
-You like them?
-They're gangster.
You know,
I'm a little bit gangster
about everything.
I see the way
that you are.
Look at the ink.
Tell me
that's not crazy, huh?
Meet my "sista"
from another "mista."
Okay, what are we
gonna make?
We're gonna do
zarandeado.
It's a Baja dish.
We're just gonna do
a little lemon,
a little naranja.
Now, this right here
is the achiote paste.
It gives that nice,
red hue.
Now watch what happens here
with the banana leaves.
You're gonna toast up
the banana leaf?
I'm just gonna
make it pliable.
Nice.
Now we're gonna
take the fish.
Add a little slurry.
I use kosher salt,
a little black pepper,
just a little citrus
from the orange.
A little lemon,
some garlic,
some onion.
And we're ready
to grill it.
Presentation side down.
So, it'll steam all the
ingredients inside of it.
There we go.
What you do is just peel it away
like a little gift.
It's packaged, baby.
Mmm!
Tilapia is not typically
very fat.
Roasting it in this banana leaf
with all that flavor,
a lot of moisture,
this is the way to go.
Mmm!
Okay!
[ Speaks Spanish ]!
FIERI: But that's not
the only seafood dish
that's swimming in flavor.
Enchilada del Mar in the window!
Let's go!
ESPARZA: 22 years ago,
I came up with an enchilada.
And I still make it.
It's called Enchilada del Mar.
It's got shrimp, scallops...
white wine, heavy cream, crab.
Let it reduce by half.
We use quesillo Oaxaca,
goat cheese.
We're gonna top it
with a seafood crema,
a little bit
this Oaxaca cheese.
And then we finish it off
with a little micro-cilantro.
And these are
Enchiladas del Mar.
Enchiladas del Mar --
the creaminess, the seafood.
One of my favorites.
If you have a chance
to come try this,
you will get a whole
'nother experience
and exposure to what
Mexican food really is --
real Mexican food,
cultural Mexican food.
You know, one of the things
I think you really gotta try
when you come down here,
is you gotta try
the chips and salsa.
[ Record scratches,
crickets chirp ]
Did I serve Guy
chips and salsa? No.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
FIERI: All right,
no standard Tex-Mex here.
But she did rock some
traditional Mayan flavors.
This is called
cochinita pibil.
Cochinita --
"little pig."
Pibil --
"underground."
Now you speak Mayan.
A hefty amount of salt.
The black pepper --
nice, coarse ground.
Then we got
some garlic.
Mexican oregano.
-[ Speaking Spanish ]
-I got some bay leaves.
We're gonna put
that achiote slurry.
So, we've got lemon juice,
orange juice,
and the achiote paste.
I just kind of pat it around,
get it in there.
So it doesn't knock
the crust off.
Right.
You're like
a "swine-estitician."
So, we're just gonna put
this banana leaf in there
to seal all the juices.
That's the plastic wrap
that they had?
Absolutely.
-A little O.J.
-A little sour orange.
Sour orange.
Let's do this.
♪♪
Oh, look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
Say hello
to my little pig.
So, you can have it with tacos
or a torta.
Or in the mano.
That's some Mayan flavors,
right there.
They're my flavors now.
[ Chuckles ]
Yes!
♪♪
Everything fires off.
You get all
of the flavor profiles,
from the sour to the sweet
to the salty, to the spicy.
My mouth is having just some
complete meltdown.
Mmm.
So, in other words, it's good?
It's ridiculous.
FIERI: This dish is still
gangbusters on the menu,
but it has an updated twist.
So, we're still doing
our cochinita pibil
the same as we always have.
The only difference is
that we smoke it.
All the ingredients
that make this robust
and bold flavor are still there.
But now the added smoke
and that crust that it gets
sends it back to that jungle
in Yucatán
where I learned
how to make this.
Cochinita pibil.
The cochinita pibil
with the smoke,
it just brought it up
to a whole 'nother level --
a whole 'nother level.
MAN: I couldn't imagine
that Silvana could
elevate the cuisine any more
than she did originally,
but she actually has.
FIERI: And the food's not the
only thing reaching new heights.
Silvana's opened a couple
of other locations.
There's one at the airport,
and there's a Gran Reserva
over in the Arts District.
I like that car of yours,
by the way.
-Not bad, huh?
-But you know what?
It might be on blocks right now.
It's okay.
I need to change those tires
out anyways.
♪♪
That's what I like to see --
"Triple D" OGs rocking it
bigger and better than before...
like bringing brand-new flavors
to a century-old institution
in the Big Easy,
adding even more
Italian inspiration
to a family-run favorite
in Northern California,
plus taking top-tier Mexican
up another notch
in Phoenix, Arizona.
And don't worry, there's plenty
more to dive into
on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
[ Mutters ]
Did you --
You're such a freaking brat.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughter ]