I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're going round two,
revisiting some of our favorite
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up.
Did you see that?!
And we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
Look at that power bite.
...it's a meat overload
all over the country.
Awesome job.
In West Yellowstone...
Here, hold that for me.
...a brand-new barbecue joint
definitely not on the radar...
-We just opened up Friday.
-Four days.
Oh, 4 days then.
That's even better.
-Yeah, 4 days.
...but ready to share
with the nation.
Dynamite, man.
Plus and old-school diner
in Nashville...
Didn't Rick James do a song
about super Greek?
Oh, that was "Super Freak."
...doubling down on
their Greek-American mash-up...
You're kind of like the UN
in Flavortown.
-I love flavor.
-...and in Denver...
You're going to mess up
the way people look at a taco.
...a Native American eatery...
He's going Barney Rubble
on that thing.
...where culture
and cuisine collide.
I've never hunched
a taco before,
but I'll do it this time.
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So this is what happens
on "Triple D Nation."
I go to check out joints
I've been to.
I go check out joints
I want to see,
and I go check out joints
that I didn't even know existed,
so we're here
in West Yellowstone, Montana,
right outside of the park,
and my wife cruises by yesterday
and picks up some barbecue.
Everybody in the camp goes nuts,
so, of course, I've got to come
and check it out.
Hunter, is this it?
HUNTER: This is it, right here,
Firehole Bar-B-Que Company.
It's amazing barbecue,
some of the best that
you're going to find.
-Rack of ribs.
-They just opened up
a short time ago,
and it's just excellent.
There you go.
WOMAN:
They have a trailer out back
where they smoke their meats,
so they can get it in here
nice and hot and ready to go.
FIERI: That trailer is property
of little Mike Shults
and his dad, Big Mike.
Your old man caught me
sniffing around the back
of the smoker this morning,
and I said,
"Well, how long you been open?"
"Two weeks."
We haven't been open
2 weeks.
We just opened up Friday.
-Four days.
Oh, 4 days then.
That's even better.
-Four days.
-Yeah, 4 days.
4 days or 4 years,
this place was so legit,
I knew I had to roll back
with my son, Hunter,
and my buddy, Paul.
Million years that he'd show up,
you know, 4 days
after he opened.
But the short time time frame
is just at this joint.
These dudes are actually
restaurant vets
with a place in Idaho
called Little Mike's,
so you could say they know
what they're doing,
especially when it comes
to brisket.
We're trimming the brisket
to about a quarter-inch fat.
Once I'm done trimming it,
I've got a rub here,
get some salt, pepper,
granulated garlic and
a little bit of seasoned salt.
It just brings out
the beef flavor,
and, you know,
it's not overpowering.
The briskets, I cook at 220
for about 12 to 15 hours,
and I use a hickory wood.
It's not too harsh.
It gives a perfect smoke flavor,
and it seems to work
for what I'm doing here.
Brisket is not easy.
I mean, that's what made
my mind up about this visit.
You like the fatty part
of the brisket?
Come on, now.
What do I look like I like?
Here's some
of that brisket.
You know this is
my brisket test.
You just give that brisket
that little tug right there,
and it just starts
to fall apart,
enough fat on there that
it still stays nice and moist.
Unbelievable.
You got the right amount of
salt, right amount of pepper.
It needs nothing.
It's really moist.
It's got really good flavor.
It's very tender.
It's got a little pull to it.
They do an awesome job at it.
-What do you think?
-I am sleeping good tonight.
Now, what do folks say that
aren't really super familiar
with barbecue when they come in,
and they see this setup
with the white bread,
the onion and the pickle?
We had to put the bread
underneath the meat.
That way, they quit asking for
butter to butter their bread.
That's the power bite,
right there.
-Yeah. See? That's --
-Onion, pickle...
-Yeah.
-...some of the brisket
and mop it
in a little bit
of sauce.
That's legit.
FIERI:
But I can't just stop there.
Those ribs are calling my name.
Here, I have the
mustard-and-pickle juice,
just to get the rub to stick
to the rib, and right here,
I use my brisket rub
that we made up earlier,
and after
we season them up,
I cook them for 2 hours
at 300 degrees.
We sauce them with some of our
house homemade barbecue sauce,
and I just kind of kick it up
a notch with some brown sugar,
some honey,
a little sweet chile sauce,
and it sweetens it up
just a little bit more.
Wrap them in foil, and I stick
them back on the smoker
for another hour.
You want to them tender,
but I don't like them
falling off the bone.
♪♪
Seriously?
-It hurts.
-I want you guys to learn.
This is an exercise, okay?
I'm sweaty.
That's a good rib.
Here, hold that for me.
All right. Go ahead.
You guys can try.
Falls right off the bone.
They're done just perfect.
It's got a good clean bite
to the bone.
They've got a good smoke.
The cut on them was good.
The meat was good, and the
barbecue sauce was phenomenal.
FIERI: Look how simple it is,
straightforward,
five smoked items,
a couple sides.
Of course, there's no-brainers
like beans,
but they've got a corn salad
that's off the cob.
We'll start with the corn,
add the cheese right in there,
onion, bell pepper, mayo,
mix everything together,
and then we will top it
with chili-cheese corn chips.
Now, see, we didn't get
the instructions
on the corn salad
when we had it.
We didn't know
that you're supposed to put
the chili-corn chips
on top of the corn salad.
Dynamite, man.
It's kind of mild,
so it complements
the smokiness of the meat.
The creaminess of the corn,
and it also had the crisp taste.
It was really good.
I'm glad that I caught you
in your first week.
-Yeah.
-Don't forget.
We show back up,
cut in line.
Uh-huh.
I'm definitely picky
with my barbecue,
and to find something
that legit
in the middle of
the Fieri Family vacation,
I have a feeling,
well, we might be hitting up
Yellowstone
a little more often.
And coming up in Denver...
You dare me?
...check out what Native
American food is all about.
I've never hunched
a taco before,
but I'll do it this time.
I guarantee you,
it will knock your socks off.
You're going to mess up
the way people look at a taco.
FIERI: Now, when I visited
Denver, Colorado,
it ended up being home
to "Triple D"'s very first
Native American joint, and
this place did not disappoint.
The dudes were awesome.
-Can I help who's next?
The energy was contagious
and the food out of bounds,
and now, it's
a "Triple D" double
since they've opened up
their second spot.
This is Tocabe:
An American Indian Eatery.
Dips with summer squash relish.
Are you familiar
with our salsas, hon?
I am.
We saw Tocabe "Triple D"
right before we moved
here from Chicago.
It was our first stop,
and now, we're total regulars.
What's a better way
to introduce
somebody to your culture
than through food?
Frybread nuggets up.
FIERI: And I got a lesson in the
lingo when I met
Osage Nation Tribal Member
Ben Jacobs...
This guy owns it
...and his business partner,
Matt Shondra.
Tocabe,
what does it mean?
It's an old Osage translation
for the color blue,
which is my mother's
favorite color.
When Guy came in.
You know, he really held
the respect
for what we were trying to do,
being culturally driven,
and that was really
important to us.
A big part of who Indian people
are is getting together
and feasting.
FIERI: So we jumped right
into their Native American
specialties like frybread...
Whoa.
Gosh, this is thin.
Toss that bad boy
right in there.
I think I just turned
into a pita.
...which was part of
that fantastic Indian taco.
Let's start with some
black beans,
chicken we made earlier,
lettuce, cheese,
make it look real pretty
with the sour cream.
Look at that power bite.
Mmm.
Frybread is the bomb with the
chicken that's been marinated.
You don't need it.
I don't need
no stinking fork.
You dare me?
I've never hunched
a taco before,
but I'll do it this time.
Just, like, went at it and
picked it up and just took
a big bite,
which was a nice compliment.
That means he likes it if
he's going to dig in like that.
I'm going to tell you
something, bro.
You're going to mess up
the way people look at a taco.
-Yeah.
-Look at him.
Look at the smile
on that guy's face.
"Yeah."
-Bring it in.
Awesome job.
What are we into now?
-Bison ribs.
Flip them over here.
We got a membrane on the back.
You don't want to
have that.
Nice...
-Butter knife.
Just nice and easy,
nice and easy.
Guy showed, you know,
a different style
on pulling off
the membranes.
The reason you use
the butter knife
is because that
paring knife will tear it.
-Tear it right through?
-There you go.
Get that right off.
We actually kind of incorporate
that and show our team members
a simplified way
to pull that membrane
off the back.
Mmm. Huge flavor, on point
with that one.
Awesome.
♪♪
Check out the dude in the back
just gnawing on the bone.
I mean, he's just --
He's --
He's going Barney Rubble
on that thing.
Mr. Rubble?
-Yes?
I saw you gnawing
on that like a dog on a bone.
Yes, you did.
Yes, you did, big and meaty,
and it's awesome.
Bison ribs?
FIERI: These days, they've got
a second location
with their bison
sporting a brand-new look --
inside the braised bison bowl.
So we're going to make
our bison dry rub.
Rubbed sage,
ground New Mexican red chiles,
dried sweet corn powder,
kosher salt, black pepper,
garlic, cumin seeds,
smoked paprika.
We like to grill it, so we get
a nice sear on there.
We'll put foil on it
and put it in the oven.
This is going to braise
for 12 hours.
Pull it apart after it braises.
FIERI: And it's all about
building the bowl.
JACOBS: Wild rice, pinto beans,
the braised bison here,
lettuce, cheddar cheese,
and the fresh squash
relish on top.
We start with yellow squash,
zucchini, jicama, habanero,
cilantro, kosher salt,
lemon juice, red onion,
and then we mix.
So now, this is ready to eat.
Braised Bison Posu Bowl.
WOMAN #2: The shredded bison is
super flavorful,
really tender,
sweet and savory.
The squash relish is a little
bit sweet, a little bit spicy.
It was supergood.
JACOBS: Guy told us that,
you know, whatever he had,
"Make sure that
you put it out there
because people are going
to want it,"
and it was very much true,
so we made a menu
that had everything down to,
like, chicken taco
and bison ribs
called Guy's Menu.
We had a lot of women come in
and thought that it was saying,
like, it was just for men,
and we're like,
"No, no, no, no!
It is not. It's for everybody."
So now, it's the "Triple D."
Killer food, great energy,
a great story,
and I'm telling you,
I learned a ton.
Awesome, man.
That's great.
-Appreciate that.
-Appreciate it.
So look out.
Besides doubling up
on locations,
they have a food truck
rolling out,
and my only question
is, guys,
is, how much for delivery
in California?
Up next, in Nashville...
That is so good.
...a little advice
can go a long way...
Guy Fieri, he encouraged me
to have my own place.
Living the
American Dream, man.
...because this Greek diner
is going gangbusters.
Look at that.
Mmm!
FIERI: Now, check this out.
There's a place
I went to in Nashville
that's a cross
between Greek...
Soutzoukakia is up.
...and a great American diner.
Got the Reuben.
Now, the chef was knocking out
killer combos in the kitchen
and working on
the American Dream,
and now, he's made
the ultimate power move
with a whole new place.
This is Athens Family Restaurant
and Bellevue Diner.
♪♪
Greek salad with chicken.
We freely admit to being
Athens junkies,
the perfect thing
for "Triple D"
because it's a classic diner
with a Greek accent.
-Kotopita?
-We love this place.
It has just grown up
with the neighborhood
and stayed true
to what it is.
FIERI: And what it is,
is an international melting pot
of Flavortown
with owners Mohamed Rasras
and Chef Adel Elostta
at the helm.
You just have a thing
about bringing
all the ethnicities
together.
You're kind of
like the UN in Flavortown.
I love flavors.
We get the call from "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
I was so excited.
FIERI:
This is the love spice.
For the love of spice,
it's called the seven of spices,
whatever you want.
-No.
Love spice is way
more marketable.
I've made a mistake before.
-No, what it is.
Mid-East mastic,
is it the sweetness?
Can I taste it?
-Taste it.
I know it's bitter,
and I didn't warn him...
[ Laughter ]
...but to give a great flavor
to the work.
FIERI: Once you get past
the bitter bite,
mastic's earthiness kicks in,
and the love spice puts the life
in all kinds of dishes
like the Soutzoukakia.
The Soutzoukakia.
-The suzuk is meatball.
-Yeah.
We're learning some Greek,
right here.
That was Greek,
right?
-Yes.
-Good.
Strip loin, Choice?
-Choice.
-There's a lot of other meats
you can grind up
to make a meatball.
That's what
make us unique.
And then what are we
going to do,
make some hot dogs
out of filet mignon next?
What's the big deal if
I'm grinding the meat sirloin?
It's going to taste good.
FIERI:
What's the big deal?
I mean, it's Choice New York
steak, man.
Most people just eat
it whole as it is.
Doesn't look very happy.
Don't be sorry for the sirloin
because you will taste it.
You just took a New York steak
and ground it up.
-That's for sure.
-That is for sure.
That's exactly
what happened.
I was here.
I witnessed it.
Season the meat --
kosher salt, nutmeg...
-Love spice?
-Love spice, a little bit.
Okay.
Chicken base?
Grated onion with the juice,
some Parmesan cheese...
-Okay.
-...red wine vinegar,
some panko.
Going to make it
like a football.
That's not a football.
That is a lawn dart.
45 minutes,
250 degrees.
Take it and dump it
in the sauce.
Enjoy.
You come to a great
American-Greek restaurant,
this is what you're
going to get -- super Greek.
Didn't Rick James do
a song about super Greek?
Oh, that was
"Super Freak."
I like them.
Great job.
-Thank you.
-Here's your Soutzoukakia.
You just can't go wrong in here.
What are we onto, boss?
We're about to make
the kotopita.
Koto, the chicken.
Koto, okay.
-Pita, pita bread.
-Like pita bread.
Kotopita.
How many times on "Triple D"
have we shot Greek joints.
No one has ever
broke it down for me.
Nice job.
You're the teacher.
You make the chicken pie
mix first.
We'll start
with some butter.
-Chicken breast.
-Cut in cubes.
Okay.
All right.
And I'm going to add
a little bit of dill...
Fresh dill.
...some chopped onion,
chopped garlic,
a little bit of kosher salt,
black pepper,
carrots, celery,
some chicken base.
Cook this down?
Let it simmer
for about 30 minutes.
Now, we're going to make
the rest of the mixture.
Yes.
It's like the beginning of,
like, chicken potpie.
-Chicken potpie.
Here we go, the Parmesan cheese,
Feta, the béchamel, some eggs.
A little extra binder,
and now you got to get into it.
-That's it.
-So now, we get the filo dough.
How did they make it
that thin?
They flip it.
Do that again.
Flipping the dough.
Throw me some music to that
and one more time.
-Flipping the dough.
-Keep going.
-Slow motion.
Flipping the dough.
Big, nice scoop,
now a little bit of mix,
press it down a little,
flip it over...
-Gracious with the butter.
-I love butter.
40 minutes, 350 degrees.
Look are those.
That thing is crunch-a-licious.
Wow.
That's not creamy.
Knocked it out
with the filo.
Kotopita.
After the "Triple D" show here,
we had people coming
from everywhere,
lines out of the door.
People basically
wanted Soutzoukakia.
They wanted to get the kotopita.
We sold so much of that stuff.
FIERI: But those weren't
the only dishes
flying out of the kitchen.
Lamburger.
Lamburger -- a little bit
of kosher salt, black pepper,
the love spice,
a little bit of panko.
Scoop just 4 ounce and
another 4 ounce -- two patties.
Why won't you just get
a bigger scoop?
Well, I don't have
bigger scoop.
-You want one for your birthday?
-Sure.
Eight birthdays now,
and I'm still waiting.
-So what goes down first?
-The bacon.
Then once I have it cooked
halfway at least,
I but the burger
on the flattop.
-Makes it sear.
-Flip this bacon over.
So you're going to fortify it
with some fat
into that lean lamb.
Now, we put some
of the charbroil?
Yes, and I put the Swiss cheese
on top of it,
then the bun here, the onion,
lettuce and Roma tomato.
Ready to go?
It's a big burger.
Crushed red pepper,
there we go.
Served with fries,
look at that.
Mmm.
That is so good.
When you say, "Great American,"
and "Greek cuisine,"
together,
that's exactly what that is.
And today, Chef Adel
is packing new lamb
dishes into his menu...
Greek-style lamb shank,
table four for Richard.
...with this next-level
Greek-style lamb shank.
I add some celery, carrots, and
onion in the bottom of the pan.
I season my lamb with salt,
pepper, olive oil.
I braise it with some broth.
It comes out within 3 or 4 hours
just tender.
-And on top?
-Orzo pasta.
I sauté my orzo with some onion
and garlic.
I add some diced tomato to it.
I lay it on top of the lamb,
and I bake it back in the oven
for another 45 minutes.
I am a lamb fan from way back.
Nobody that I know of serves
a lamb shank like this.
It's killer.
It's terrific.
WOMAN #3:
The meat is very tender,
comes right off the bone.
The orzo is not something
you would typically expect.
It's just a nice mixture
altogether.
-350.
-350, yeah.
Good job looking at the camera.
Take over the show.
See you later.
Good-bye.
Put the shades
on the back of the head.
There you go.
Good-bye.
Guy Fieri, he encouraged me
to have my own diner.
You're putting
all the love into that one.
-That's right.
-I like it, man.
Great job.
-Thank you.
FIERI: And guess what?
He listened.
Just wait until you see
what he's doing
across town when we come back.
You've got a lot
on your hands here, brother.
You just wait.
You wait until you see
what's coming.
A few years ago, I stopped
into Athens Family Restaurant
in Nashville.
Now, when I say, "Nashville,"
what kind of food you thinking?
Exactly, great American food,
but when I put a little
"Triple D" spin on things,
what do you get?
You know it, great American
and Greek cuisine
where Chef Adel was living
the dream cooking up
Greek-American favorites,
but he had even bigger dreams
and opened this joint
across town, the Bellevue Diner.
Guy Fieri, he encouraged me
to have my own place.
It worked out,
a dream come true.
Both Bellevue and Athens
are going strong
and look a lot alike,
but the food, well, that's
a whole different story.
We went more Americanized
with our menu.
I want to add to it some classic
dishes that you have at home
that your grandma
used to make for you.
FIERI: He's talking about
stick-to-your-ribs dishes
like the bomb breakfast,
Reubens,
and even beef Stroganoff.
MAN #2: It's a comfort food.
With the pasta,
it's one of my favorites.
But he didn't totally
get away from Greek.
Get me a bifteki sandwich.
The bifteki sandwich
is a sandwich you get
in Greece out of those
souvlavakia shops.
I started with ground beef
and ground lamb
with some grated onion,
garlic, salt, pepper.
I make it supreme,
which I grill it
with tomatoes, onion,
peppers, and mushroom.
I wrap it together
with a homemade tzatziki
and pita bread.
WOMAN #3:
It's very, very tender.
The pitas are very good here,
the best in town.
MAN #3: You can taste the onions
and the peppers in there,
and it tastes very authentic
like in Greece.
FIERI: And there's a few things
you can find
at both joints
like this classic
Greek number, ktipiti.
A ktipiti for Alexandria.
Ktipiti is spicy Feta dip
with some roasted peppers.
FIERI: And that's no
store-bought Feta.
I make the cheese
with whole milk, some rennet.
I salt it up.
Within 4 days, it's hardened up.
It take it.
I grate it.
I roast red bell peppers.
I blend it, add in some olive
oil and lemon juice,
cayenne pepper,
blend it together.
You serve it with hot pita.
MAN #4: The ktipiti is just
a little spicier
than pimento cheese,
extremely creamy.
You can taste the peppers in it.
I think that's what gives it
a little different flair.
A little bit of spice and a
little bit of heat is so good.
Give me one egg, over-easy.
Chef Adel realized
his American Dream
through this place
and through Athens.
Coming right now.
Being that Adel's dream
was to open up the restaurant
and be successful as a chef,
he's done very well for himself.
Kotopita.
FIERI: And the "Triple D Nation"
has come calling to both joints.
They stand here next to me
on the picture
and take picture of me,
like I'm, you know,
Brad Pitt or something.
[ Laughter ]
You're doing exactly what
we call talk about,
and that's living the --
You're living your dream
You're living
the American Dream, man.
-I am living my dream.
-Congratulations.
And that dream is
coming true.
That's awesome.
Man, it's so fantastic seeing
all these joints
living their dream,
like the Denver spot dishing out
real-deal culture cuisine,
and the Greek-American mash-up
doubling down in Nashville
and even the brand-new
killer barbecue spot
I staked out in the middle
of West Yellowstone.
They're all part
of the "Triple D Nation,"
and we've got plenty more
to catch up on.
I'll see you next week.
I'm trying to help here.
-Time out.
-No. You don't -- I need you.
Turn around. Show them.
Show them the shades.
Show the shades.
♪♪