You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That place you went to
in that one town
that served that one dish,
how are they doing
after 'Triple D'?"
You know what? I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
Wow!
A Cuban joint in Miami
speeding things up.
Hello Gov'ner.
Beef short-rib's up!
FIERI: Korean barbecue in Denver
taking over the town.
That's tasty.
A Hawaiian hangout in Seattle
saying "Aloha"
to a sweet, new addition.
The camera just
about bit my finger.
And a bonus, I'm introducing
you to an Italian spot
I hit every time
I'm in Chicago.
Just wait till you
meet the owner.
[ Both laugh ]
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors...
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So I'm here in the River West
neighborhood of Chicago
to check out a joint
I've been coming to for years,
and you've never seen
on "Triple D."
But, boy,
it's got a great story,
it's got a lot of history,
it's got incredible food,
and it's got an owner
you'll never forget.
This is La Scarola.
♪♪
Look at this!
Oh!
MAN: Food is just
absolutely incredible,
and it's just got
a great neighborhood feel.
Coming to La Scarola reminds me
of being with my grandma
on Sunday evenings.
All right, guys,
round number two.
WOMAN: Well, this is the kind
of a restaurant
that you'd expect
to see Guy,
because it has the divey-ness
but the good food
and everything else --
the whole picture.
Sausage and peppers.
So let me set
the record straight,
now, this place
has never been on "Triple D"
but there is a poster
on the wall.
And that's because my brother
from another mother,
Armando Vasquez,
makes me feel at home
every time I walk through
the door.
It's the place I go to
every time I come to Chicago.
Now, how many years it been
since I've been coming here?
Oh, I want to say 12.
Ever since the first day we met,
we became really good friends.
FIERI:
And the first thing I learned,
is that my friend
serves up scratch-made Italian
with a heaping helping
of hospitality.
What you do,
how you treat people,
the way you make people feel
when they come here,
is really the lost art
of being the Maitre D'.
Gnocchi frodemar.
And you take care of folks.
You know everybody.
You remember all the details
of what table and where it was.
I know what
they want to eat,
I know what they like
to drink, yes.
Do you know
what I wanted today?
Yeah, the Veal Chop
alla Gabe.
That's what
you always get.
Two Veal Chop alla Gabe
coming right up.
FIERI: Veal Chop alla Gabe
is a hands-down winner.
One of the biggest hits
on the menu.
We use the 10-ounce veal chop.
Pound it paper thin,
dust it in flour.
The reason we call it
Veal Chop alla Gabe,
there used to be a guy years ago
who wanted me to pound
the veal thinner and thinner
and his name is Gabe.
And I say, "You know what,
we call it
Veal Chop alla Gabe."
And we're going to have the chop
right on top of the potatoes.
Bon Appetit.
Whoa!
This is gorgeous.
The beautiful part though,
but no fryer.
No fryer, it's pan-fried.
You can't put that in the fryer.
No, you kill it.
Not covered in batter.
No, the crust is
very thin.
That veal chop...
It's great man.
Hope you're hungry, sir.
MAN #2: The garlic and lemon
sauce play off of the breading
and the veal so perfectly.
It's to die for.
VASQUEZ: A question that
I always get, "Are you Italian?"
Not even close.
Where'd you come from?
Oaxaca, Mexico.
He gets his Italian inspiration
from his business partner,
Joey Mondelli,
who's creds include cooking
for the one and only,
Frank Sinatra.
Plus, Armando's been putting
his own stamp in the kitchen...
We make it with love!
FIERI: ...by mixing in
some Mexican flair,
like in their Pasta Lorenzo.
Shrimp, chicken,
sun-dried tomatoes,
and chipotle
tomato wine sauce.
I was the first guy using
chipotle peppers
in tomato sauce.
Little bit of spice,
not too much sauce.
People look at you
like crazy.
"Why would you make something
like with Italian food?"
But it's a twist, you know?
It's your own touch.
Fantastic.
The pasta's cooked perfectly,
the shrimp's not overdone,
and you don't see enough
farfalle, the bow-tie pasta.
You don't see it enough.
-Right.
It was my favorite
when I was a kid.
Yeah.
Are you going to get
some of this, or just me?
No, I'm trying to lose weight,
but I will.
Don't lose weight
on today's show.
Pasta Lorenzo!
Smells so good!
Every dish is
absolutely incredible.
It's always fresh,
pasta especially is al dente
all the time --
the same al dente each time.
Eggplant Parmesan going out!
Pick it up!
When somebody comes here
the first time,
what do you recommend
they have?
Always the Pasta Fazool.
Pasta Fazool!
FIERI:
That's his signature soup,
usually made with marinara.
But of course, Armando's got
to do it his way --
swapping in Romano instead.
Pasta Fazool, beans and pasta.
Fantastic.
Pasta's tender,
the beans are firm, it's hearty,
you definitely get
the salty of the cheese,
but not overly salty.
Mmm.
Fantastic.
Pasta Fazool going out!
Pasta Fazool, it's amazing.
It's a very, very hearty soup.
It's almost a meal in itself.
The food is dynamite,
but I really come back
just to hear the laugh.
[ Laughing ]
The laugh is --
as soon as you hear it,
you never forget it.
[ Laughing ]
You're the best, brother.
-Thank you so much.
Appreciate it.
-Thanks man.
♪♪
I am so glad that I can finally
introduce my brother, Armando
to "Triple D Nation."
And man, I tell you what, that
laugh, it gets me every time.
Now coming up...
I'm dying over here.
I'm going to wither away.
...another chef I could never
forget for his killer food...
Legit, buddy.
-All right, man.
-Legit.
...and the do.
That's impressive.
So it's 2015, we're right
outside of Denver, Colorado...
Beef short-rib's up!
...where Chef Joe
had hair up to here,
and a righteous, all-you-can-eat
barbecue buffet out to there.
Plus he had dozens
of scratch-made sides
that took forever to cook,
but were well worth the wait.
Outstanding.
So what's he up to now?
Well, he's got four locations.
This is Dae Gee Korean BBQ.
Kimchi chicken!
I recently moved
to Denver from Los Angeles,
and I've eaten a lot
of this type of food there.
But it was kind of great
to find something
that was so authentic
in the middle of the country.
I need some cucumbers
off the line!
I originally saw this place
on "Triple D."
It's more than just Korean
barbecue, it's really good food.
Unlimited barbecue!
FIERI: When I went to check out
Chef Joe Kim's Korean barbecue,
I ended up getting
a little distracted.
Normally, you know,
I'm the only guy
in the show with the real lid.
I mean, I'm going to put a bag
on my head after this.
Don't say anything.
We were the first
Korean barbecue
restaurant on "Triple D."
Somebody says, "Okay,
I'm going to go to Dae Gee."
And they go,
"Oh, that place you..."
KIM: Pig out.
So "Dae Gee" means
"Pig" in Korean.
There was a few things
I was expecting him to tell me,
"Pig out" was
not one of them.
You know, we did
the unlimited barbecue.
How many side-dish items
are there?
We have eight.
You know, there's a lot
of different types of meats
that come out with it.
We're going to make
the beef bulgogi first.
What does
"bulgogi" mean?
"Bul" means fire,
and then "gogi" means meat.
-Fire-meat.
-Yeah.
This is the sauce
for the Bulgogi?
Right.
Onions, pineapples...
-Apples?
-Yeah.
...soy sauce, sugar,
black pepper,
and most importantly,
Soju.
-Soju.
-Kind of a Korean spirit.
"So-ju" got to put it
in there now?
Yeah.
I was so nervous.
I was like, "Why's he keep
on repeating this
'So-ju want
to put a little bit more?'"
So-ju just put
a little bit in?
Yeah.
You know, it took me
a couple rounds
and I was like,
"Oh, I got it."
Thank you.
I'll be here all week.
♪♪
What meat is this?
-Rib-eye.
-Slice it thin.
-Mm-hmm.
How long are you going
to let that marinade?
-12 hours.
-Next step, what are we making?
-Kimchi.
-How would you equate to Kimchi.
Is that like the french fries
to the burger?
I mean the Kimchi is kind of
like the staple
behind a lot
of Korean food.
-Absolutely.
-What's next?
We're going to make
some Kimchi pancakes.
-Of course we are.
-Yeah, yeah.
We got through about
two or three of those,
and he was like,
"Hey, when are we going to eat?"
And then he's like, "I don't
think we're ever going to eat."
So actually there's another side
that we're going to make...
Of course there is.
That's just -- That's awesome.
We'll eat next week.
It just took forever.
My hair's going to look
like yours
if we don't hurry up
and eat.
Yeah, you eat enough
Korean red peppers and
it's going to look like mine.
-Okay.
He would have just been a little
frustrated at that time.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Mmm.
The bulgogi's righteous, man.
I love that you used
the rib-eye.
Kimchi cake,
pretty gangster.
You have the variety.
You take the time
to make everything...
-Yeah.
-...and make it yourself --
make it with
your family's recipe.
That's the difference.
I wish I could rent, like,
two extra arms.
These days, Joe's up
to four locations
that go beyond the barbecue.
And good-old Korean favorite,
new to the menu,
is the fully loaded Bibimbap.
It's the thanksgiving meal
of the Korean barbecue.
The spinach, bean sprouts
right here,
we got a zucchini,
carrots, shiitake mushrooms,
the cabbage that we've cut up,
and the radish,
marinated rib-eye,
and we're going to
put it on the grill.
Garnish it with an egg.
Table number five, Bibimbap.
Bibimbap is great, the crunch
from the vegetables,
kind of savory
from the meat.
You have a combination
of five,
six, seven different flavors
that all ends up in one bite.
FIERI: And don't forget
all the original gangster
sides it's served up with.
Plus you can pile on
with a newcomer,
the zucchini pancake.
KIM:
Korean name is Hobak Jeon.
"Hobak," which means zucchini.
"Jeon" means pancake.
Americans are very big on pizza.
And this is kind of
the closest thing to pizza
in the Korean culture.
So we got the zucchini,
put the flour in, carrots,
onions, and the egg,
scoop of water.
So you got to mix it
to get a certain texture.
And then once the thickness
is good,
We'll go right to the pan.
Is there such a thing
as an international house
of Korean pancakes?
Might have to
think about that.
The zucchini pancake
is super-crusty
on the outside
and super-soft on the inside.
Fresh veggies,
little more savory,
then you kind of get,
like, a little zing
and zest with the sauce.
-Really nice job, buddy.
-Thank you.
If you're going to have
a haircut like that,
you better back it up.
-Yeah, absolutely.
-Legit, buddy.
-All right, man.
-Legit.
Keep cooking.
♪♪
Happy to see that Joe is
still rocking the sweet do.
I mean, it's almost
as impressive as his food.
And coming up...
Wow!
Now, you know what else
is impressive?
This chef in Miami,
who's getting his food
to the "Triple D Nation"
even faster.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: So back in 2014,
my really good friend,
Chris, from Scully's Tavern
in Miami
told me about a new joint
down the street with burgers
and tacos like
I've never seen before.
It's called Latin House.
Yellowtail up!
FIERI:
Well, after the first visit...
Wow!
...things got so good
that Latin House spun off
into a second restaurant
serving the same great food,
only this time quicker.
They want one carne,
one chicken, one carnita.
You got to love the name,
this is Madlove.
♪♪
They always have the best food,
it's always the freshest,
it's cooked perfectly.
MAN #3: They have the best
burgers in South Florida.
Chef M., he's a magician.
He's incredible.
Two burgers --
one Cuban, one original.
FIERI: Chef M. is owner,
Chef Michell Sanchez,
who opened Latin House
as a triple-threat
of American, Mexican,
and Cuban cuisine.
SANCHEZ:
My wife is Mexican,
and so a lot of our dishes
are that Cuban heart,
with the little sidekick
of Mexican flair.
All right,
let's do this.
So we're doing
the chimi-burrito.
While that's going,
we'll take the tortilla,
throw it on the flat-top --
give it a nice little warm-up.
-That's it?
-Voilà.
We got our three-cheese blend
you want to start on the base.
Chuchi rice.
That's my mom's nickname,
is Chuchi.
This is a fried plantain
that's ripe.
So we roll, squeeze the ends,
roll again, push it in --
always make sure you push it in
'cause it will blow up on you
when it goes and gets dropped
for the flash-fry.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
you're going to fry it?
I'm going to drop it.
♪♪
Oh, a chimi-football.
I'm going to
slice it open.
Look at that.
Our fresh pico de gallo.
The chimi-burrito.
Don't do the
fork-and-knife thing.
Do it the right way.
Like that.
[ Laughs ]
You get the salty beef,
and this deep, rich beef flavor.
And then you get
that super-seasoned rice.
And all the sudden that fried,
sweet plantain comes in.
I mean, wow!
Before Guy showed up,
everybody was eating the burrito
with a fork and knife.
And I make that one comment,
and literally every day
that you go there
now you see everybody holding
a burrito in their hands.
Everybody's lost
all their manners completely.
And another thing I fell
right into, their hot sauce.
All right, so this
is our lobster lollipops.
So I'm explaining
the three sauces to him...
Mango habanero, the aioli,
and the garlic cilantro.
Normally, people like to work
their way up in heat levels.
He went, like,
grabbed the chunk
and went deep down --
pure mango.
Yeah,
that's going to hurt.
Very, very hot.
It's like a good burn.
Wow!
-Yeah.
-Hello, Gov'ner.
To this day, people ask, as they
come into the restaurant,
they're like,
"Whoa, governor.
Whoa, governor!"
Chef,
you rocked the house, man.
Thank you, man.
Thank you so much.
Your lobster lollipops.
FIERI: These days, Latin House
has gotten folks
lining up out the door.
Even people in Miami
that hadn't heard of Latin House
were coming to Latin House.
So he opened up a second house
for those who just can't wait.
Madlove is a sped-up version
of the Latin-American mash-up
he's been known for.
Madlove is a greatest hits
of Latin House.
All right, let's get
those burgers down.
Let's get that bread.
FIERI: Plus, he's laying down
some new tracks
on this rocking menu
like their poke tuna tacos.
So we're going to use some fresh
ahi tuna, star anise, hoisin,
a little ponzu,
fish, and oyster sauce,
and we're going
to let that marinate.
FIERI: And watch their trick
to bringing in the heat.
This is our candied jalepeño.
We take sliced jalepeños,
give it a really,
really nice coating of sugar,
put it in the oven,
we're going to bake it.
After we've taken it out
and it's cooled off,
we're going to go ahead
and put them in the blender,
add a little bit of vinegar,
and some more sugar.
♪♪
Sweet, [ Coughs ]
a little too hot.
That's exactly what you want.
We're going to put
a little bit of candy jalepeño,
now we're going to get our
pickled onions, chipotle aioli,
now you have our
tuna sushi in a taco.
Hi guys, I have here your Champ
and your Original
and your poke tuna tacos.
WOMAN #2: My favorite is
the poke tuna tacos.
It's so fresh.
It tastes like it was
just caught off the boat.
Three pokes all day.
MAN #4:
He had the little jalepeño,
little relish that
makes it a little spicy.
Madlove up!
We're known for our burgers.
We won all these
burger competitions.
FIERI: Like his national
award-winning Champ Burger.
It's a 60/20/20 blend
that we have.
It's chuck, short-rib,
and brisket.
Champ burger has a maple bacon,
and then we put
the candy jalepeño
to give it
that little bit of a kick.
And there's your Champ.
I made a point of coming here
just to try the Champ Burger.
Cheese just melts on top of it
in just an ooey-gooey goodness.
No wonder you've been
so successful.
You have
no boundaries.
So much has spawned from that
one day of being on TV.
Blows my mind, man.
So what was I thinking, going
straight for the mango habanero?
I don't know.
And putting his food
on the fast track,
that just means that I get it
to my mouth faster.
Now that,
I can get on track with.
Now coming up...
This is traditional
Hawaiian.
-Yes.
-Okay.
Outside of Seattle,
a Hawaiian hideaway
that isn't so hidden anymore.
That's tasty.
Now, I'm a big fan
of Hawaiian food,
but you probably
already know that.
And I always love
hitting up the island.
But I found a legit,
I'm talking real-deal,
Hawaiian joint right here in
Seattle, keeping both the food
and the dancing
as real as it gets.
And guess what, that
Aloha Spirit is still alive
and well at Bobby's
Hawaiian style restaurant.
♪♪
Kobe ribs and salad.
Oh, my gosh!
The camera just
about bit my finger.
MAN #5: A lot of people saw
the "Triple D" episode
and they said,
"Oh, what's Bobby's about?"
And I said, "Oh, you're in
for a treat."
Enjoy, you guys.
WOMAN #3:
It brings me back to Hawaii.
The food is wonderful,
and the people are great.
SERVER: Enjoy!
FIERI:
This joint is a "Triple D" OG --
One of the first.
And Chef Bobby Nakihe is still
owning it in the kitchen.
We're going to make the most
famous Hawaiian dish of all --
Kalua pig.
So what do we start with,
a little pork-butt?
Pork butt,
and I'm going to season it.
Let me guess,
Hawaiian salt.
Now what is -- whoa, whoa,
whoa, what is this?
You got a palm tree?
-Banana leaf.
-Banana leaf?
And bananas is good.
Smell like banana?
And now,
all I'm going to do is
just cover it
with banana leaf.
♪♪
Wow!
Look at that!
It's soft,
just tears apart.
That's tender, man.
That's tasty.
What island
did you live on?
-Moloka'i.
-Mokoli?
No,
Mo...lo...ka'...i.
Moloka'i.
He's laughing back there.
Now what
are we going to make?
Well, I am going to make,
what we call, lomi lomi salmon.
"Lomi lomi" in Hawaiian,
means "To mix."
So "lomi" means to mix?
Yeah,
to mix everything.
So we call it
mixy-mixy salad?
We're going to
take some salmon,
going to add some tomatoes,
diced onions...
-Some green onions.
-...green onions, Hawaiian salt,
and just mix it.
It's like a salsa.
Mix in the salmon
with the other ingredients.
This is traditional,
traditional Hawaiian.
-Traditional, yes.
-Okay.
The dishes that me and Guy made
are still on the menu
and people still come in
to order those dishes
because they've seen it
on the show.
What do you think?
-That's tasty.
-Yeah.
-Lomi lomi.
-Mixy-mixy.
When "Triple D" came,
we couldn't handle
the amount of people
that came to the restaurant.
I'll take the mochi chicken
and the Kalua pork.
We were open seven days, and we
were getting burnt out because,
I mean, people just kept
coming and coming and coming.
So I warned him,
and they finally had to move.
Now, their new place
is a monster
compared to the old one,
with a kitchen
that's three times the size.
Teri pork.
And that means that Bobby
gets to expand
on what's coming out of it.
SERVER:
Mochiko chicken.
FIERI: Plus, he's blowing things
up with a bakery next door
filled with island-style
guilty pleasures.
NAKIHE:
I always wanted to be a baker.
And so I decided to take
a chance and open up a bakery.
FIERI:
And his go-to is the Malasadas,
kind of like a Hawaiian donut.
Sugar, evaporated milk,
flour, eggs,
the yeast, and vanilla.
Get a scoop,
place it right here.
Just going to be
really, really sticky.
Now we let it rest for a while,
and it's ready for a fryer.
FIERI:
They're fried on paper to keep
them from sinking into the oil
before they get all sugared up.
Normally, a Malasadas
only comes sugared.
But what I did, was I added
my own cream filling.
SERVER #2: Malasadas.
NAKIHE: It's fluffy, it's airy,
it's crispy on the outside,
but yet soft on the inside.
WOMAN #4: The Malasadas donut is
so light and delicious,
it takes you to another place.
MAN #6: It reminds me of when
I was a little boy in Hawaii
and grandma used to bring me
back some stuff from the store.
I absolutely love it.
♪♪
This is exactly what you would
find back home in Hawaii.
FIERI: Well, I'm going to take
you up on your offer,
which you're going
to fly me to Hawaii
so I can check to see
if this is exactly how it is.
I'll get back to you
in two weeks.
Actually, we're going back
home next month -- September.
So bring your exchange student
from Santa Rosa.
[ Laughter ]
"Look what we brought!"
Great experience.
-Thank you.
I'll waddle
out now to the car.
[ Laughs ]
So that's what it's all about --
checking in
on killer-Korean in Denver,
a Hawaiian oasis in Seattle,
lights-out Latin
in little Havana,
but also new joints like one
of my favorite Italian gems
in Chicago.
Now, watch out, Chef Armando.
The "Triple D Nation"
is coming for you,
and we'll be cruising
the country going for more.
[ Laughs ]
There's one laugh.
Two.
[ Laughing ]
Three.
[ Continues laughing ]
Yeah, that's four.