Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for
America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Bring it.
...we're divin' into some
righteous regional recipes.
I can't get this in my face
fast enough.
Like red-hot Mexican
in California.
This is how it comes out
to your table, this inferno.
Smoking sandwiches
in San Antonio.
Really impressive.
Thank you, brother.
Plus crazy good Creole...
Oh, you do that right.
...served up by one
outstanding octogenarian.
Imitated by many,
duplicated by none.
The real deal.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in Santa Rosa,
California,
just a few miles from my house
to check out a...
Santa Rosa, California.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Now, my buddy, Chef Cesar,
who works for us
at Knuckle Sandwich,
has been telling me about
this amazing Mexican restaurant.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
I really appreciate it.
The translation part, though,
I needed help on the inside.
I got this part out here.
-Okay.
He's been telling me
it's authentic,
and they're cooking food in a
way that we haven't seen before.
This is it, Taqueria Molcajetes.
-Oh, good Spanish.
-[ Laughs ]
Three tacos
and steak ready.
-Everything tastes so homemade.
-Mixtos.
It reminds me of Mexico.
The food is just exactly the way
it is down there.
Specifically, Guadalajara and
Michoacán, the Mexican regions
where owners Zacarías Martín
and Dionisia Valdovino
are getting their
culinary inspiration.
Ask them what makes Michoacán
food so different.
And remember, there's a lot
of people
watching that
understand Spanish,
so don't say anything
about the fat guy
with the bleached hair
wants to know.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
And onion.
And don't forget the joint's
namesake, the molcajetes,
which is the traditional
Mexican mortar and pestle,
which they're loading up
scorching hot.
Molcajete mixto.
Chorizo, cheese, chicken.
It's good, very nice.
All right, so this
is the spice mix,
or what do you call
the sauce inside of it?
Salsa molcajete.
Orange juice.
-Oregano.
-Bay leaf.
-Cloves.
Pimiento.
Black pepper.
-Cumin.
-Salt.
So the original way that this
would have been done
would have been
in a molcajetes.
Now we're making
a tomatillo tomato mix.
-Got it.
-Combine onions and garlic.
-Water.
-How long is this going to go?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
15 minutes,
and now the chilies.
-A little bit of oil.
-And garlic.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
So everything is
15 minutes around here.
So we have the vinegar-herb
mixture that we made.
We have the tomatoes,
the onions,
the garlic, the chilies,
and now everything
comes together.
And this is all for
the salsa molcajete
that's going to go inside
one of these cauldrons of heat
that are cooking
in the back.
♪♪
You can taste a little bit
of that vinegar in the back,
a little bit of the heat of the
chili, but it's really smooth.
Now we're gonna
put it together.
Chorizo.
They make it here.
You make the chorizo
and put it in the casing here?
Yep.
I'm going to tell you
something, Cesar.
When they're making
their own chorizo,
they're blending
their own spices,
I think that's
the difference.
Beef and chicken.
Butter.
-Always that many shrimp?
-Eight.
-[ Whistles ]
Salt and garlic.
You know what, Cesar?
I am so sorry.
I didn't have him
make you one.
It's okay.
Just watch me eat it.
it's already cooking again.
-Salsa.
This is how it comes out
to your table, this inferno.
Chorizo and cheese.
You make
the tortillas also?
All handmade.
And it comes with rice
and beans also?
Yeah.
♪♪
Without question,
one of the best
Mexican food experiences
I've ever had.
I can't get this in my face
fast enough.
All the aromas that comes out
when you put
a hot sauce into a --
-That's exactly what it is.
It brings all the flavors out.
Outrageous.
This exceeded my expectations.
One more bite, Cesar,
and then you're done.
Really?
[ Laughs ] Really?
Molcajete mixto.
You get a taste of
every single ingredient.
And when it's combined in this
delicious sauce, it's explosive.
It's amazing.
-Three tacos and steak ready.
FIERI:
From the moment I walked in,
I knew this was going
to be the real deal.
The energy, the enthusiasm,
the Mexican culture and food.
It is what's going on here.
Which means traditional tacos.
Your al pastor tacos.
The tacos pastor is delicious.
I'm getting the real deal.
What are we doing now?
OROZCO:
We're going to start with the
adobo, the sauce for the pork.
Oil. Onion.
Chilies. California.
Guajillo.
The bay leaf.
-Chocolate.
-This is Mexican chocolate.
It's got little cinnamon,
little chunks of sugar.
Black pepper.
-Cloves.
-Oregano.
-Orange juice.
Salt, red coloring,
white vinegar.
Cook this down,
puree it.
Now the adobo is ready
to marinate the pork.
Piece by piece,
lay down the sauce, put it down.
Every day.
So how long is this
going to marinate, chef?
At least 12 hours.
And then we put it
on the rotisserie.
A pineapple on the bottom,
and a pineapple on the top.
So this is how it is,
old school, down in Mexico?
Somebody's making tacos
all day long,
so he's chopping
and spinning it.
Onion. Salsa.
-And that's it?
-That's it.
♪♪
This is as close to the Mexican
street taco experience
that I've ever had
in the United States.
It's tender,
not over-seasoned.
You love the freshness
of the cilantro and the onion.
-Want more?
-Of course, I want 85 more.
Al pastor tacos.
I can have tacos al pastor
every day.
The seasoning is great.
The meat is delicious.
So, if I gave you a taco
from Mexico City
and one from
Taqueria Molcajetes.
I would probably think they're
both from Mexico City.
-Dos ensaladas.
-[ Speaking Spanish ]
So it's natural,
it's unique,
and the sauce --
-Fresh.
It's fresh.
Not bad, huh?
Carne asada.
MAN:
I really, really enjoy this.
It's almost like comfort food,
if you wish.
I like to come very often.
FIERI:
The foods you're making, the
experience people are getting.
It's the real deal.
Outstanding.
-Thank you.
Up next, a taste of New Orleans
in San Antonio.
That is every bit of what
you want a gumbo to taste like.
Where I get right into it...
A little more work than
I anticipated doing today.
-A man of knowledge.
-[ Laughs ]
...with an unforgettable
character.
-The food is great.
-But the love is greater.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Don't speak to me
in Spanish.
I'm already having
enough difficulty
keeping up with English.
♪♪
So I'm here in San Antonio,
Texas,
on the east side about
five minutes from downtown.
And right on the back side
of Fort Sam Houston.
Now, after 9/11,
they closed the gates,
and a lot of the businesses
in this area, they took off.
But if you're looking
for a restaurant
where the chef is living,
loving, and laughing,
and cooking, and rhyming,
and teaching, and winning,
all at the age of 89,
then this is your place.
This is Ma Harper's
Creole Kitchen.
♪♪
Cajun sausage.
I tried everything on the menu,
and it's all delicious.
Po' boy right off
of Bourbon Street.
The atmosphere and the people
make it even better.
FIERI: Which all begins with
the illustrious Ma Harper,
who got into
the restaurant biz
after retiring
from her first career.
You worked at
the Air Force base?
Yes, I worked on
an F-15/F-16 Unified.
I worked on the 107, 108,
106, fuel pumps,
I've worked on the wing,
and I've worked in electronics.
Get out.
Well, you don't have to get out.
It's your house.
You can stay.
I'll leave.
-Guess what -- If I get out,
I'm going to
take you with me.
I like it.
These days, she's putting to use
what she learned cooking
for 15 siblings
growing up in New Orleans.
I especially like the gumbo.
When we go to New Orleans,
and we try all the gumbo,
they don't compare
to Ma Harper.
So, we got
the whole enchilada.
-Without the tortilla.
-Let's hit it.
Water and the crabs.
Not the shrimp yet.
'Cause the shrimp
will overcook.
Thank you. Let somebody know,
that's how you cook.
Chicken. Don't do that.
[ Buzzer ]
-Oh! Why?
-Let me teach you.
Okay, come on, teach me.
...for pots.
You want to lose your job,
beat my pot.
Do that?
Oh, look what you just did.
That's what I'm saying.
Metal, when it's hot,
tears it up.
Spank that baby and say,
"Be good."
Onion,
add the bell peppers.
I gotcha.
Sausage.
Dehydrated bell pepper.
Okay.
Dehydrated shrimp,
parsley, thyme.
Time to what?
If you got time to lean,
you got time to clean.
[ Laughs ]
Garlic powder.
My spice mix.
The ham.
Black pepper.
Okay.
Chicken broth?
-Yeah.
-Now the roux.
Cajun seasoning.
Our gumbo files --
We call it filé, but it's --
Filé -- file --
Bring this to a boil.
We'll drop the shrimp?
-Yeah.
What are we going to
serve this with, Ma?
-Ma Harper's cornbread.
-You're going to do a cornbread.
Cornmeal, flour, sugar,
baking powder, and salt.
Never crack an egg
over your food.
I agree with that.
'Cause you don't know
what hen's sitting in it.
[ Laughs ]
Oil, milk.
Go egg again.
Oil.
-Gotta be fast today.
Milk.
Another egg. Milk.
A little more work than
I anticipated doing today.
No dry spots.
That's what I call
a man of knowledge.
[ Laughs ] It's called a guy
that didn't have a mixer
for a long time.
Pour it.
[ Gasps ]
I like that karate move.
I don't know how you made
that spoon jump right in there.
What temperature
we putting that in?
400 for an hour.
-Toothpick test?
-Not necessary.
I use eyesight.
That's the way
we're gonna do it.
-A little honey and butter?
-Try it, you'll like it.
Imitated by many,
duplicated by none.
Oh, that's good.
So now we're gonna do
some gumbo, rice.
Finishing it with
Cajun seasoning.
That's good.
Talk to me.
Don't even act like
I need to talk to you
because you know
how good this is.
That is every bit of what
you want a gumbo to taste like.
All that big grits flavor
coming out of that seafood.
It's silky.
It's tender.
I can't eat this
fast enough.
Thank you.
Here's your gumbo.
I like the flavor.
All her special ingredients.
The seasoning, the gravy.
Oh, cornbread.
It has that just sweet flavor.
Wonderful to crumble up
in my gumbo.
She feeds
the body and the soul.
WOMAN:
She gives people second chances.
When it's hard for them to go
get a job somewhere else.
She trains 'em,
and a lot of 'em go off
and get their culinary degree.
I do hearing impaired.
I do anybody that has made
a mistake,
and they feel
there's no more.
I was taught, if you don't work,
you don't eat.
So my theory is to help you
to readjust to life.
It's a great mantra.
Love from Ma's heart
finds its way into the food.
Pork chop,
red bean and rice.
Fried pork chops. They're
tender, crispy, very delightful.
The red beans and rice,
can't go wrong with that.
Now we're into
the famous pork chop.
You start with your flour,
a little black pepper.
Poquito salt.
We throw a little Spanish
in here every once in a while.
-Onion.
-Powder.
Paprika to give color.
Garlic.
-Creole seasoning.
Give it a whisk.
We got pork shoulder.
Tenderize it a little bit.
-Yeah.
-I gotcha.
Flour, water.
And then flour
one more time?
I use my fryer, 300.
What are we going to
serve it with, Ma?
Red beans and rice.
17 minutes.
That's how long that took.
Why 17 minutes?
'Cause you don't want to eat
the hog raw.
Try it,
you might like it.
♪♪
That's a good chop.
This is a lot of flavor
and just a little bit of batter.
♪♪
Oh, the red beans
and rice are good.
Oh, you do that right.
That's a meal by itself.
The food is great.
But the love is greater.
The real deal.
Here's your pork chop.
The pork chop is excellent.
It's perfectly cooked.
The beans are soft
and smooth and creamy.
Corn dogs and fries.
The closest I could come
to being in New Orleans
is coming to Ma Harper's.
Amazing-licious.
Amazing-licious?
Watch out.
When Ma gets a hold
of amazing-licious,
she's going to make
a whole new rhyme about it.
Red bean and rice,
everything nice.
Give me a one-liner
before we go.
89 in line and dying.
Going to live 129
and in good health.
Remember that.
Let's go, Ma.
Coming up, we're sticking
in San Antonio...
There you go.
...for smoked meat
sandwiches...
That's fantastic.
...with some surprising spins.
-I'm following your lead.
-You'll like it.
♪♪
So I'm here on the east side
of San Antonio, Texas,
in an area known
as Dignowity Hill,
where an East Coast boy
comes out to Texas
to go to school for finance.
And what happens?
He falls in love.
With barbecue, that is.
And now he's doing it
his own way --
smoking meats
and making barbecue here
at Dignowity Meats.
A bologna.
Dignowity's just this great,
unassuming place
that serves up
this amazing food.
I got a pit beef.
Hanging out here,
having beer and barbecue.
This is a fun place.
Beer and barbecue in Texas,
who would have thought.
-Yeah, who would have thought.
-Two smoked turkey caprese.
What makes Andrew stand out
is the attention
that he puts to each sandwich.
FIERI: 'Cause chef and owner
Andrew Samia
has mad love
for the deli sandwiches
he grew up with
on the East Coast,
and he's adding
a San Antonio spin
with Texas-style
smoked meats.
I wanted to smoke
everything here in house,
take everything
from start to finish,
and just kind of really do it
the old-school way.
Where'd you
learn to cook?
Just being broke
in college,
watching a lot
of Food Network,
Alton Brown,
a lot of "Triple D."
Smart guy.
It's a lot of really
classic items,
but everything's different
from the ordinary.
Your Burnt End Melt.
MAN: The Burnt End Melt
has burnt ends,
mac and cheese,
melted cheese,
and a little sliver
of pear slipped in there.
It's really phenomenal.
What are
we making first?
This is going to be for our
Burnt End Melt sandwich.
Prime Angus brisket,
and we're going to --
Prime?
Hang on a second.
[ Whistle blows ]
Angus in its own right
is fantastic meat.
Prime is what you find
in high-end restaurants.
Yes, sir. First just going to
hit it with some kosher salt.
Okay.
And then coarse ground
black pepper,
Cajun spice,
and granulated garlic.
Really giving it a gracious
helping of this.
Because what's going to happen
is you'd take the knuckle,
and you'd cut these ends off,
and then you'd go again.
Well, it would look like
these burnt pieces
'cause you reseasoned it
and resmoked it.
Yep.
But you want to talk about
the pièce de résistance.
So for you to be making
a whole sandwich out of this,
that's a give right there.
What kind of wood
we smoking with?
Hickory chips.
Brisket's down.
What's up next?
We're going to make
our barbecue sauce.
Ketchup, brown sugar,
molasses.
Pineapple juice.
A little sweetness,
a little bit of tang, as well.
Water.
Liquid Smoke.
I got a waft of it as soon
as I moved it.
-Yeah, you smell that?
-Dry mustard?
Yes, sir.
Granulated garlic.
Cajun spice
and kosher salt.
All right, so let this simmer
down, simmer down now.
The brisket's cooled,
and now you're gonna cube it.
Yes, sir. Now we're going to
season and sauce it.
Cajun spice,
a light brown sugar, our sauce.
And now mix it all?
Absolutely.
This is going to go
into the smoker on 250
for about an hour
and a half to two hours.
-And then it's done?
-And then it's finished.
Just waiting on the mac
and cheese. Let's see it.
Unsalted butter,
all-purpose flour, cold milk.
So make a basic Béchamel.
I'm just going to add some
sharp cheddar cheese,
kosher salt, black pepper,
and our Cajun spice.
Add the parboiled elbows.
-Absolutely.
-Let's put it together.
-We got our mac and cheese.
-Where's the bun coming from?
A local baker here in town.
Smoked brisket burnt ends.
Sliced pear.
Everything's making sense
except the pear, bud.
I'm following your lead.
-You'll like it.
Sharp cheddar cheese,
a little more barbecue sauce.
Take a little bit
of the top out.
Wow, you're really helping
on the carbs, aren't you?
That's so it's a little
health-more conscious.
Health more?
A little more
health conscious.
Health more conscious.
Come on down where it's
health more conscious here.
And then on the press.
That's what I'm talking about.
Bread on mac and cheese.
With fruit.
Does the pear play?
Don't talk in the middle
of a backswing.
Remember when
you were a kid,
and you'd wait
for that report card?
Yeah.
I'm waiting right now.
-How does that feel now?
-It's pretty nerve-racking.
I'm going to
tell you something.
I'm going to be
100% honest.
That's fantastic.
-Thank you, Chef.
-This is full of high notes.
It's studded with
these big pieces
of this super tender,
but textural brisket.
Then you get
the creamy cheese.
Then you get the little soft
bit of the noodle.
The pear does give a nice
little refreshing.
-A little crunch?
-A little crunch,
a little sugar.
It gives
a little raw relief.
This is a lethal weapon.
You'd have to register this
in Flavortown.
We'll get its ID card,
don't worry.
-Really impressive.
-Thank you, brother.
Got a Burnt End Melt.
MAN: The Burnt End Melt
is really great.
I mean,
it does have burnt ends.
They're very caramelized,
juicy on the inside.
-The pear seems odd.
-It does seem odd.
-Yeah, but it's like candy.
-Tastes delicious.
-Great sandwich.
-Side of corn bake.
The food's spot on, lights out.
Hard name to say, but it's
an easy place to eat at.
How did the name
come about?
Dignowity Hill is
the neighborhood we're in.
It's during the Texas
Revolution.
Santa Ana had his troops
here on the hill
because he could see
all the way down to the Alamo.
Got it.
I'm so much more educated now.
MAN:
It's really convenient because
it's very close to downtown,
but it's not in the center
of everything
where it's going
to be super crowded.
I got to walk away
from this one.
When we come back, we're going
to do a real-deal Reuben.
Reuben with
a side of corn.
The Reuben's great.
The pastrami is delicious.
I've never had another one
like it in San Antonio.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're on the East
Side of San Antonio, Texas,
hanging out at a funky
little joint called Dignowity.
That's the mountain
we're on, right?
The knoll?
-Dignowity Hill.
-So you can see the Alamo.
-You can see the Alamo.
I'm learning all about history
and making some great barbecue.
FIERI:
And it's all happening inside
a funky former burger joint
where Chef Andrew
is combining his passion
for sandwiches
and smoked meats.
Two Reubens coming out.
MAN: The Reuben itself
has pastrami, cheese,
and it's a very
unique flavor.
Sauerkraut, a nice, toasted,
perfect bun.
What do you got?
So the pastrami's a little
more traditional.
Same cut of beef.
-So prime brisket.
We're going to make
a real basic brine for it.
Put water, brown sugar,
coriander seed, kosher salt.
There you go.
Yellow mustard seed.
-Interesting.
-Pickling spice.
Curing salt.
-You got it.
Bring it to a boil
so everything dissolves.
The flavors kind of wake up
a little bit.
Get it cool and pour
it over the brisket.
How long is this
going to brine?
Over the weekend,
normally three or four days.
All right, how long's
your weekend?
So a little rinse
has happened to this,
but you can see some of
the pickling spice still there.
Now we're going to
season it.
Whole black peppercorn,
coriander seed, white sugar,
and some granulated garlic.
-It's like a sundae.
A hodgepodge of different-sized
granules in there.
You know how
to spell hodgepodge?
-No, I don't.
-I don't, either.
I use it, but I don't know
how to spell it.
Into the smoker, 225 for about
12 to 14 hours.
Dig it.
So this is the pastrami
that we just smoked.
Look at that.
♪♪
Okay. Later.
Healthy amount of coriander.
The quality of the meat
comes through.
Typically, you throw this
on the slicer.
Yeah, typically.
-Ribbing it out?
-Absolutely.
Look at it, though.
Great crust.
All right, let's build it.
Some good Swiss cheese.
Our house-smoked pastrami.
And then we're going to toast
this up,
heat up the pastrami,
melt the cheese.
House Russian dressing,
sauerkraut,
top it off
with the bread here.
-That's all she wrote?
-That's it.
♪♪
The fact you're bringing this
to San Antonio
speaks volumes
about this relationship
that you have
with smoking meats and barbecue
and just your whole energy.
It's not super hard to do,
but it's labor intensive.
It takes a lot of time.
But I tell you, when you're
in the mood for sauerkraut,
pastrami,
a little Russian dressing.
Do I have any right there?
-A little bit right there.
How long was it there?
How long did he let me --
Dynamite.
-Thank you, Chef.
People are going to be
showing up here
trying to buy this pastrami
by the pound.
You better watch out.
-Hey, we're ready.
We're ready.
Bring it.
Reuben with a side
of our mac and cheese.
The Russian dressing on this
Reuben sandwich
kind of blends
all the flavors together
with cheese and the bread.
The toast is really good.
It complements the meats.
A salumi and a pit beef.
WOMAN: We have people
from out of town.
We're always, like, "You have to
come try Dignowity."
What you're doing and how
you're treating it, great job.
Thank you, brother.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
Real deal.
Imitated by many,
duplicated by none.
Imitated by many
and duplicated by none.
Remember that.
-[ Laughs ]