Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
...we're heading straight
to carnivore city...
Oh, my goodness.
...for this major meaty mash-up.
That's a big burger,
boss.
Like an old gas station
in Little Rock...
I hear that story every day.
Don't you?
...filling folks up
with the bomb bison...
We're goin' nuts now,
folks.
...and a Vietnamese joint
in Santa Rosa, California...
Let 'em talk
amongst yourselves.
...that's a Fieri family
favorite.
I wanted to see that
my hometown joint was
doing it the right way,
and you're crushing it.
And a funky smoke shack
in Sonoma...
Watch out for this guy.
...queuing up
a mega mouthful.
Get those arms out...
rotate back...
release the jaw.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
Yeah, I'm just
pulling up right now.
So, what do you --
Oh, hey, what's up?
I'm here in my hometown
of Santa Rosa, California,
at a Fieri family favorite,
introduced to us
by my nephew Jules.
What's goin' on, "Triple D"?
Now, Jules, when you come here,
what do you normally get?
To start things off,
we'll take some egg rolls,
some shrimp spring rolls,
extra peanut sauce,
maybe a rare-steak pho,
barbecue-pork combo
with double meat.
[ Chuckles ]
Is that
gonna be enough?
Of course
that's enough.
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is Simply Vietnam Express.
♪♪
I have the barbecue-pork
combination with rice.
You get good-quality food,
and it comes out quick.
Curry rice, Mom.
-Rice bowl.
-Okay.
A lot of places say
they're family owned,
but you don't necessarily see
any of the family.
You do see a lot
of the family here.
FIERI: Like Jon Nguyen
and his mom, Be.
Who started
the restaurant?
We did -- Me and my mom,
my sister, my dad,
my other sister,
and my brother.
And where did you
learn to cook?
Vietnam.
You were a chef
in Vietnam?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
FIERI: And brought with her
that know-how
for serving up
Vietnamese favorites.
Combination pho
for table 12.
Hands down,
the best pho I've had.
It's fresh.
The broth is wonderful.
FIERI: So, how do you
make great pho?
We start off
with beef cold cuts.
The marrow
is what really --
That's what
you're looking for.
That's what I'm looking for,
the bone marrow.
Do you really
put it in by hand,
or do you dump the whole thing
and it splashes everywhere?
Dump the whole thing
and it splashes everywhere.
Splash!
I do it when it's cold,
but it's been boiling.
Oh, well, that takes
all the fun out of if.
So, how long's
it gonna take?
I actually let it sit
for 24 hours.
24 hours this sits?
I'll let it sit 24 hours.
What's next?
Chicken carcasses.
And this is the recipe
that your mom followed?
Yes.
Back in Vietnam.
We'll boil it
and skim it,
take the impurities
off the top.
Correct.
Now we drop the brisket.
Yes.
And flank steak.
Once that goes
for eight hours...
Now you drop in
the goodie bag.
The seasonings.
-Dry coriander.
-Star anise?
Real cinnamon.
Roasted ginger, onion.
You prefer just tying it
versus a string?
Yeah.
In the water.
And let it simmer overnight.
Then we'll remove
the flank steak,
the brisket,
and the spice bag.
Once reduced down,
then we will add some sugar.
-Salt and...?
-Ginger.
And more onions.
We add more water.
And then we have
the difficult decision --
Do we want meatballs?
Do we want flank steak?
Do we want raw steak?
Do we want brisket?
Do we want...
The choices,
the choices.
JON:
One handful of noodles.
I'll have
the steak/brisket/meatball.
So I start with the brisket.
Five pieces of meatball.
And the steak is
the eye of the round?
Correct.
Green onions.
Cilantro.
And white onions.
Got it.
My mouth is watering.
Let 'em talk
amongst yourselves.
Mmm!
Oh, my goodness.
It's light,
it's refreshing,
but the depth of flavor
is outstanding.
Mmm!
It's everything
I wanted it to be.
I cook pho, I've been to
some great pho restaurants.
I wanted to see that
my hometown joint was
doing it the right way,
and you're crushing it.
I have the pho combination
noodle soup.
What do you think
of the pho?
It's a huge portion.
Super yummy.
I love being able to put
my own fresh ingredients inside,
and I like the noodles.
So, I'm lucky enough
to get the representative
from the Fieri family --
my mom, Penny.
What do you think makes
this place so great?
It's always consistent
and fabulous.
And they give you
so much.
Trust me.
"Trust me"?
You're gonna love it.
Beef combo coming up.
I like to come here for the
different variety of the meats,
'cause the marinades
are really good.
JON:
Barbecue-pork combination.
The grilled pork is very tender,
really flavorful.
Let's get it. How do
we make the barbecue pork?
So, we start off
with minced garlic,
garlic powder,
lemongrass.
A lot of it.
Vegetable oil.
Sesame oil.
Teriyaki sauce.
Honey.
And sugar.
And mix it up.
Now, is this
pork butt?
Pork collar.
-Thinly sliced.
-Uh-huh.
Let it marinate
overnight.
Beautiful.
Next we're
gonna make...?
The egg rolls.
I need to know
how to make these,
'cause I eat 50 of them.
[ Chuckles ]
We start
with minced shrimp,
ground chicken,
and ground pork.
Mix that up?
Hoisin sauce.
Black pepper.
Bring in the garlic?
Salt.
Minced garlic.
Sesame oil.
Carrots.
Then we have taro.
Really? I thought
it was mushrooms.
Green onions.
White onions.
And sliced super thin.
It'll cook
all the way through,
and it won't have
the raw vegetable.
-Correct.
-Got it.
Then we have
glass noodles.
Different than
the rice noodle.
Correct.
Sugar.
And then we finish off
with an egg.
And the egg works
as a little bit of a binder.
Correct.
We'll start rolling
the egg rolls?
Mm-hmm.
Drop it in the deep-fryer
for eight minutes.
Grill the pork.
Are you sure
that's just one order?
One order.
See, I think
what happens is,
every time I send
my nephew Jules
to come pick
this order up,
he eats a little
on the way home.
'Cause it never looks
that big, Jules!
[ Chuckles ]
Barbecue pork.
Add three shrimp.
Egg roll.
I finish it off
with a little
cooked green onions
with garlic.
And there you go.
Mmm!
Marinated garlic shrimp.
Correct.
So tender.
And the egg roll --
shrimp, chicken, pork.
The taro is a big key
right there.
Crispy, delicate,
great balance.
And not oily.
-Not oily.
-That's the key.
It's a very simple menu,
simple ingredients.
Correct.
But you and your family
handle the discipline
to make it outstanding.
Just like this pork.
It's tender,
super flavorful.
You get more
than you can eat.
It's all scratch-made,
and really fast.
Excellent.
♪♪
The pork is always
really tender.
Fresh shrimp,
just perfectly cooked.
MAN: The egg roll's really good
because it's nice and flaky.
You can taste how fresh
the vegetables are.
A good buddy of mine, JT,
that I have known for years.
What do you think
of what they're doing here?
The portions are great,
the food's great.
It's fantastic.
Curry chicken with rice
coming up.
When you're traveling up 101,
you've got to stop in here
and check out what
Vietnamese food is all about.
If you come
to the Wine Country,
you're looking
to have a good time,
I don't have my restaurants
here anymore,
but don't worry,
Jon and his family
are gonna
make it happen.
Great job.
Thank you, buddy.
Awesome.
FIERI: Up next...
We're diggin' into barbecue
up the road in Sonoma...
Oh, yeah.
...at a spot
throwing Cali flavor
in Southern-fried...
This is not your grandma's
fried chicken.
...and building up
a skyscraper sandwich.
You have to have
adult supervision to eat that.
Five, four, three, two.
Yeah. So, no, I'm just --
[ Door handle rattles,
laughter ]
I just got locked out.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Northern California,
on Highway 12.
Santa Rosa's that way,
Sonoma's that way.
Now, listen,
up and down this corridor,
you can find just about
any food you can imagine,
but if you're gonna tell me
you're gonna find
old-school, real-deal,
stick-burning,
outrageous barbecue?
Well, I'm gonna tell you what --
When pigs fly.
Oh, that's it.
This is Cochon Volant.
♪♪
What are we gonna have?
Uh, brisket for sure.
WOMAN: We're in the heart
of California Wine Country,
and we have a gem here.
ROB: You're gonna go
with the ribs?
-Got to do it.
-Great.
What do you guys want
on the side?
Barbecue at its finest.
FIERI: And when Chef Rob Larman
and his wife, Lizzy,
dove into the barbecue biz,
they went for a roadside shack
with a fancy-sounding name.
Cochon Volant.
That's French for
"the flying pig."
I've been cooking
since I was 17.
Fine dining.
But I've always had this love
of fire and smoking and --
FIERI: You do
old-school stick-burners?
We don't use any gas.
This is about as old-school
Southern barbecue joint
as you find them
in Northern California.
With Sonoma
at its heart.
Which means there's
a NorCal twist throughout,
whether he's smoking
or frying.
Apple-chili-brined
fried chicken.
It's got an unusual amount
of spice to it.
It's unique and delicious.
Let's see it.
Granny Smith apples
in our cider vinegar.
Sugar.
Honey.
Kosher salt.
Molasses.
A boatload of it.
Garlic.
Pasilla chili paste
that we make here.
Water.
I don't care what you do
with this chicken
after this brine.
Jus would be good
in this. [shoe]
Jus would be good.
Depends on who was
wearing them before.
Thank you very much.
How long are we gonna
let that brine?
It'll go overnight.
Is there
any resemblance?
Big brother/
little brother?
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna make
our rib rub.
-Okay.
-Paprika.
Powdered onion.
Dry mustard.
Sugar.
Kosher salt.
Powdered garlic.
Fennel seed.
And fresh-ground
black pepper.
Fennel seed?
That's the key.
Yeah,
it's a bit of a surprise.
Now, the chicken dredge
is going to be...?
Rib rub.
Cornmeal.
Flour.
-Dredge it.
-Fry it.
That's a big order.
Nobody goes hungry here.
We're gonna add a slice
of our chili-cheese cornbread.
Gorgeous.
That's my kind of cornbread.
Nice cheese on that.
Mmm!
Fried chicken.
[ Chuckles ]
Nice little crunch
on the outside.
Not overdone.
The breading is just
a little complement.
But where
you might believe
that you would miss
some batter
and some crunch,
it is far...exceeded
by the depth of the flavor
in the brine.
Well, thank you.
I mean, you want to talk about
flavorful chicken?
Bro.
You get the apple.
Sweetness.
You get the vinegar.
I like
that much vinegar in it.
Wow, that's good.
I can't fit it in my mouth
fast enough.
[ Chuckles ]
This is not your grandma's
fried chicken.
This is a chef's
Wow!
Sam, we've got
fried chicken for you.
Best chicken I've ever had.
Perfect.
Nice and juicy on the inside.
I would have this all the time.
[ Chuckles ]
ROB:
Here comes the sauce.
I really like Rob.
He's always got
a smile on his face.
Just friendly
and a community guy.
He does everything
for everyone.
FIERI: No better example
than during the wildfires
that tore through
our hometown of Santa Rosa.
You spent a week
feeding firefighters
and folks
that were displaced?
I was on the phone
to all the powers that be,
"Where do you want us?
We're loading the truck."
You're awesome.
All the firemen who worked it
called it "the 10-pound fire"
because they were
fed so well.
Here.
Try a little brisket.
Thank you, Rob.
FIERI: And speaking
of feeding folks well,
how about trying all this 'cue
piled up on a burger?
It is massive.
Always cooked to perfection.
FIERI:
That's when we come back.
I don't know
what I want --
a napkin or water
or a place to lay down.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hangin' out
in Northern California,
right between Santa Rosa
and Sonoma,
at Cochon Volant,
the Flying Pig.
When pigs will fly.
How about a stick-burning
barbecue guru like yourself?
I've got a pound of nice,
fatty brisket for you.
Come and get it.
Spectacular barbecue.
FIERI: And if you can't
decide what to get,
don't worry, Chef's Rob's got
you a sampler solution.
Got a WTF Burger.
You get brisket, you get pork
shoulder, bacon with the burger.
You can get a pork cake on top.
FIERI:
And it's late-night inspired.
I was watching
the "Fallon" show.
Right.
Great show.
Jimmy, you da man.
And you come on and put
this burger in front of him,
and I turned to my wife
and I go,
"I'm putting this burger
on my menu."
And when you named it WTF,
it means "What the Fieri"?
What the Fieri.
-Yeah. Exactly.
-Exactly.
So, this is
our prime brisket.
You're doing
prime brisket?
Sure.
Typically only at
your high-end steak houses
are you getting
prime beef.
Why wouldn't you?
Hat's too tight.
[ Laughs ]
Fresh-cracked
black pepper.
And then I go with salt.
Kosher salt.
This sets normally
24 hours.
We'll let that salt sink
way down into there
and build flavor.
What temp are we running?
220.
And we only burn almond.
For how long?
-About 14 hours.
-Okay.
We're gonna do the brine
for the pork shoulder.
It's a brine
that you would use
on a French dish
called petit soleil.
Watch out for this guy.
So, we're starting with
kosher salt, sugar, garlic,
juniper berries, cloves, thyme,
whole black peppercorns, water.
You just bring it up to a boil
and turn it off.
Brine's cool?
This is like the tea
of Flavortown right here,
my friend.
It is.
Now the pig's
gonna take a bath?
So, we've got
a boneless pork shoulder.
It'll sit on brine
for about three days.
-Whoa.
-Yes.
When it comes out...
Pat it dry.
Rub it with our rib rub.
And then it's gonna go
into the smoker
for nine hours at 220
over almond.
All right, Chef.
So, here's our brisket.
Ooh.
♪♪
Oh.
Sorry.
We got more.
Great bark.
Super tender,
not dry.
That's delicious.
We season our hamburger
with salt and pepper.
A little
hamburger dressing --
mayonnaise and some
of our Carolina sauce.
Okay.
Caramelized onions.
Things are getting
dangerous.
Cheddar.
We've got a little pork,
brisket,
a little bit
of our barbecue sauce.
Okay.
House-cured maple bacon.
Our fried
chipotle-pork cake.
This is
a chipotle sauce.
And that's
the What the Fieri Burger.
Forget about it.
Oh, yeah.
That pork nugget --
that'll hurt.
Get those arms out...
rotate back...
release the jaw.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
[ Exhales ]
That's a big burger,
boss.
It's totally stupid,
isn't it?
Yeah. You're getting like
a pound and a half of meat.
I love the brisket.
I love the pork.
I love the bacon.
Love the onions.
Yeah.
Yeah, you have to have
adult supervision to eat that.
'Cause that flavor right there,
brother -- wow.
ROB:
Got a WTF for Christina.
It's everything you've
ever dreamed of in a burger.
Unbelievable brisket.
I mean, it is super special.
I've traveled a lot
over the country.
Okay.
I would put up Rob's barbecue
against anybody's.
-Here's a little taste.
-Thanks, boss.
FIERI:
I've lived in Sonoma County
for 20-some years,
been up and down this corridor
a bunch of times.
I'm glad
I finally found it.
-Thank you, man.
-Well done, my friend.
Watch out for this one.
You're gonna need
a new gym membership.
FIERI: Coming up,
a retro service station
in Little Rock...
It's off the chain.
...serving up righteous
Mexican comfort combos.
That's one
you got to try.
♪♪
I think, on "Triple D," you have
come to expect the unexpected,
so try this one on for size.
I'm in Little Rock, Arkansas,
to check out a joint
that is doing a funky spin
on Mexican food.
It's owned by owners that didn't
know each other too well
that opened up
in an old 1960s gas station.
This is The Fold.
♪♪
Tacos and churros
for table 50.
The Fold does a great spin
on classic Mexican.
It really puts
a gourmet touch
on a lot of dishes
that we all grew up eating.
One waffle down.
FIERI: We'll call it
Cali-Tex-Mex comfort fusion,
knocked out by Chef Alex Smith,
co-owner Bart Barlogie,
and their culinary matchmaker.
You two didn't
know each other?
-We did not.
-Nope.
But you two both knew
the silent partner
that got
the ball rolling?
Yep.
Three strangers gonna embark
on a restaurant
in an old gas station.
-Correct.
-Yeah.
Boy, I hear that story
every day.
Don't you?
Their food is a little more
exotic than any other place.
The bison burrito.
Everybody does beef, but you can
come here and have bison dishes.
They definitely take it
to the next level.
FIERI: So, what are
we gonna make?
The bison
for our bison burrito.
We use bison just because
it's a little bit leaner.
I think it has
a different flavor
than the ground beef.
We'll make
the seasoning.
Okay.
-Chili powder.
-Got it.
Oregano.
Cayenne pepper.
Red-pepper flake.
Paprika.
Garlic powder.
-Cumin.
Onion powder.
Apply it
to the bison now?
We do.
And salt and pepper,
as well?
Yes.
Next step?
Our red-salsa base.
Just tomatoes.
Okay.
Roasted onions and jalapeños
and garlic.
Fresh cilantro.
Lime juice.
Mixture
of cumin and salt.
And then
immersion blender?
It is.
Okay, nice talking to you.
I'll be back here.
Yeah.
Stand back.
And when this salsa sets up,
it even gets better.
It's usually best
on day two.
It's good
on two minutes.
[ Chuckles ]
Next up?
The ranchero sauce.
Our red salsa base.
Tomato juice.
Dried árbol chilies.
More cumin salt.
So, this simmers
for about two hours.
And that's the sauce
that goes in the burrito?
Yes.
What will be next?
Shout it out
when you know the answer.
We're ready to throw stuff
on the burrito.
Don't get so excited.
Try to dial it down
a little bit if you could.
On a 1 to 10, you're
probably hitting like a 0.3.
This is level, like,
9 excitement for me.
This is 9 for you?
You should see me
on a regular day.
I'm barely awake.
[ Both laugh ]
We start with
the Pepper Jack cheese.
Then the bison.
Black beans.
Caramelized onions.
More cheese?
Got to make it cheesy.
So, we just
cut it like that.
Sauce just over the top.
Little queso fresco
and chopped cilantro.
And that's all she wrote?
That is it.
♪♪
I'm gonna
tell you what --
The bison is so lean
that that extra cheese
really helps it out.
It's got a good balance.
The crust on the seared burrito
is awesome.
But the kicker to this bad boy
is this ranchero sauce.
Dynamite burrito.
Lots of flavor, great texture,
quality ingredients.
Done the right way.
Thank you.
Bison burrito for 30.
It's a really hearty burrito.
That red sauce gives it
a little kick at the end.
I try to save this side of it
for lunch tomorrow
so I can have
this experience twice.
Right.
MAN: The Fold is definitely
one of my favorite spots.
It still has this awesome
old-gas-station feel to it.
What did it take
to renovate this?
It was still in operation
as an old gas station.
[ Stammers ] People were still
coming here as a gas station?
-No, as a service station.
-As a service station.
There were people
working on cars right here?
Yeah, right here,
right here, yeah.
Huh.
FIERI:
But now they're only working
on fueling up the menu,
throwing a wrench
into familiar favorites.
The cornmeal waffle.
WOMAN:
If people say "waffle,"
I would think it's made out of,
you know, normal flour.
But this was quite unique,
and I like it.
Pork, salsa, egg, waffles --
my favorite things.
What else you got
up your sleeve?
A farmer's tan.
You do have
a farmer's tan.
So, now we're gonna
make the pork
that goes on
the cornmeal waffle.
You start with annatto.
-A sauté paste.
-Yes.
Dried oregano.
Orange juice.
And white vinegar.
Okay.
Garlic.
Just blend that
until smooth.
Are you gonna
"Chucky" the pork?
What does that mean?
Oh.
A little more calmly,
obviously.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay. So just score
the top of it.
We rub it with a mixture
of oregano and salt and pepper.
Pour some of this
over the top.
Orange juice.
Don't wash that off.
It'll go in the corner.
Onions.
Bay leaves.
Chicken stock.
Cover it
with banana leaves?
It marinates
for eight hours?
Mm-hmm.
What temperature
for the oven?
300.
-For how long?
-Eight hours.
Ladies and gentlemen at home,
this is my official guest host.
His name is Trevor.
So, he has phoned in
to help make
the waffles with us.
Hi.
What are we making next?
We're making
the cornmeal waffle.
All-purpose flour.
Cornmeal.
Baking powder.
Salt.
Sugar.
You know that we whisk the
dry ingredients first, right?
Yeah.
Because you're
a baker.
Add buttermilk.
A little melted butter?
Eggs.
Trevor,
tell the chef good luck.
-Good luck.
-Thank you.
And say goodbye to everybody
in "Tripe D."
Bye!
That's a pretty dry
batter.
What's the batter?
What?
[ Chuckles ]
What's the "batter"?
Oh.
You're just blowing up on
the inside with that one, huh?
[ Chuckles ]
Cornmeal waffle.
Top it with
a little of the pork.
A little?
It's the South.
That's our version
of "a little."
Tomatillo salsa.
Sliced green onions.
Queso fresco.
Some cilantro.
It usually comes
with an egg.
Egg?
Why would you wreck it
with an egg?
Just imagine
a sunny-side-up egg there.
Oh-ho-ho!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
The pork
is super tender.
A lot of great flavor.
And your creativity
is way out there.
A lot of people haven't had
savory waffles.
That's one
you got to try.
The cornmeal waffle.
WOMAN: It's just
a delicious combination,
and not something that
I would've thought to do myself.
I love this place.
It's fantastic.
You're missing out
if you don't come by The Fold.
Can I get a..."whoo"?
Whoo.
We're goin' nuts now,
folks.
It's off the chain.
[ Chuckles ]
Good job, Chef.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry --
there's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm!
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
[ Laughter ]