Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
...we're serving up a true
Flavortown flavor fest...
That's why we do
"Triple D."
...like a farm‐to‐table treasure
in Sebastopol, California...
making bomb bacon...
They are the Smithsonian
of swine.
...and blowing up the waffles...
That's a dish.
...an empanada emporium
going big in San Antonio...
That's a lotta empanada.
...and a legit taste
of Chicago...
This, I hear,
is the real deal.
...deep in the heart of Texas.
Ohh!
That's all
right here, right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐Ins &amp; Dives."
♪♪♪♪
So, I'm here
in Northern California
on the west side
of Sonoma County
in a great little town
known as Sebastopol
to check out a restaurant
that's owned by two
of my favorite chefs ‐‐
one you've seen on "Triple G"
a bunch of times.
And these two are all about
community and farm‐to‐table.
This is it ‐‐
Zazu Kitchen + Farm.
Pimento mac!
It's one of the most
innovative restaurants
in all of Sonoma County.
Kimchi tacos.
WOMAN: We have a lot of great
farm‐to‐table concepts,
but I don't think anything
is quite as special as Zazu.
John, I need
a butcher board.
FIERI: And the owners
are willing to prove it.
My friend Duskie Estes is a chef
who's competed and judged
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
And her husband, John,
is the real deal
and a charcuterie champ.
But how do you
describe Zazu?
Authentically farm‐to‐table,
'cause we farm ourselves.
We raise our own goats,
sheep, pigs,
chickens, ducks,
rabbits, and ‐‐
Can you say that
five times fast?
‐Yeah, I can.
‐Probably not.
I don't think
she can, either.
But we have two food styles.
He does rustic Northern Italian,
and I do playful Americana.
"Playful Americana."
She didn't use the
word "whimsy." That
would've been worse.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you, John.
FIERI: And sometimes
the rustic and fun collide,
like in this crazy concoction.
Black Pig
bacon‐in‐the‐batter waffle.
Bourbon gelato, bacon toffee,
bacon baked into the waffles.
Absolutely guilty pleasure.
What are we
gonna make today?
‐A bacon‐in‐the‐batter waffle...
‐Okay.
...bourbon gelato,
bacon toffee.
‐It's a half‐hour show.
‐[ Laughs ]
John, you're gonna start.
We're gonna make bacon.
Brown sugar, kosher salt.
Chili flakes 'cause everything
should have some heat.
Black pepper.
And then the curing salts.
Rub this pork belly with this.
How long is it gonna sit?
Two weeks, sometimes three,
and that's really
what distinguishes bacon we make
from other people's bacon.
It just sort of concentrates
all that goodness.
Then they will go into a smoker
for 12 hours on applewood chips.
This area of Sebastopol is known
for the Gravenstein apple.
Is that the reason
for the apple, or...?
Yeah, so, the fruitwoods
tend to be softer and sweeter
than something
like hickory or oak,
which is
a super‐smoky smoke.
‐It's a super‐smoky smoke?
‐Super.
‐Super‐smoky smoke.
‐It's whimsical.
Not hitting it
with heavy hickory.
Yeah, we're not trying
to cover up ‐‐
Hitting it
with heavy hickory.
Look at that.
The Triple H?
‐There you go.
‐Bacon toffee.
Sugar, water, butter.
All of it together.
‐What temp?
‐300.
‐Bacon salt?
‐Yes.
‐Can I just have a bowl of that?
‐Yeah, you can.
I mean, you can have that one.
I got more in the back.
Spread it out
on this pan.
Let it cool, break it up.
This goes on top.
What's up next?
Bourbon gelato.
Do you guys make
a lot of gelato here?
Yes, a lot of gelato.
‐A lot o' gelato?
‐A lot o'.
This is, like, the easiest
thing in the universe.
If you have
a gelato machine.
‐From Bologna, yeah.
‐That's baloney.
Milk, sugar, vanilla beans.
Bring it to a boil.
I'll take
the vanilla beans out,
and then I'll temper it
into the egg mixture.
The yolks just kind of
bump up the fat. Bourbon.
This goes into the gelato
machine how long?
12 minutes.
The only thing we have left
to do is make the waffle.
‐Yeah.
‐Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Are you ready?
You don't ask, "Are you ready?"
if I was ready.
‐I might be ready faster.
‐Make the waffle.
Buttermilk, egg yolks
from our chickens.
Local eggs.
Oh, really?
‐Butter.
‐Flour.
Cornmeal.
Sugar, salt, baking soda,
and baking powder.
And we whip the whites.
Drys into wets.
Whipped egg whites.
Let's waffle it up.
Add the bacon.
Buttermilk waffle ‐‐
first "B."
‐Okay.
‐Second "B" ‐‐ bourbon gelato.
Third "B" ‐‐ bacon fat toffee.
You ready?
‐Please.
‐Maple syrup.
♪♪♪♪
The bacon inside of the waffle.
That's the real surprise.
Because that salt cuts through
a lot of the sweetness,
but so does that bourbon.
That bourbon gives
a nice little tang,
nice little acidity
in there.
The gelato
is not overly sweet.
It's like a deconstructed
salted caramel ice‐cream cone
with bacon on it.
This is rustic, playful,
Americana.
Whimsy.
You forgot whimsy.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
It's dynamite.
‐Bacon waffle.
‐It's amazing.
You get the sweet and the savory
and the salty all at once.
Two heroes of
Northern California ‐‐
We have firefighter Luz,
and we also have the one
and only Evelyn Cheatham,
the leader of a great program
called W. O. W.,
working with kids
and developing them
through the kitchen.
Luz, what do you think?
The waffle is great.
It's delicious.
How do you describe
this restaurant?
CHEATHAM:
The people who started it...
Well, I would call them nuts
because ‐‐
Nobody's arguing.
[ Laughter ]
They won't serve anything
that's not number‐one quality,
which is crazy,
but that's this business.
FIERI:
And of course that includes
one of Duskie and John's
specialties ‐‐
that killer Black Pig bacon.
MAN: The pig is the foundation
of this place,
and the Black Pig bacon
that they make is just amazing.
How many bellies are you going
through in a month here?
JOHN: We probably
go through 40.
They are the Smithsonian
of swine.
Dude, that's a good one!
That's a keeper!
FIERI: Now, that pig
may be a cornerstone,
but this place is built
on more than just meat.
When we come back,
we're gonna go vegetarian.
Good deal?
Good deal.
Porcini noodle.
Porcini noodle stroganoff.
It's really wonderful pasta.
WOMAN: The fresh wild mushrooms
inside are just so delicious.
They don't make me miss meat,
and I'm a carnivore.
Making some pasta.
See you in a bit.
♪♪♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Northern California
on the west side
of Sonoma County
in a town known as Sebastopol
with two of my favorite chefs ‐‐
husband‐and‐wife team
owning the famous Zazu ‐‐
Chef Duskie, Chef John.
They are real‐deal
farm‐to‐table.
MAN: In addition
to their own farm,
they're supportive of all
the other farms in the county.
FIERI:
Which includes local meats...
Black Pig BLT!
...and the bounty
of the county.
Porcini stroganoff!
Porcini noodle stroganoff
is by far my favorite dish
on the menu.
The mushroom grower
is from right up the street.
The arugula is amazingly fresh.
They make the noodle in‐house.
Let's make the pasta.
All right. Flour, semolina,
and then porcini powder.
So, dried porcinis
that are ground up.
‐Whole eggs.
‐Knead this.
And how long are you
gonna let this rest?
A half an hour,
40 minutes?
Are we going to
roll this out with a pin
that comes from your grandmother
from Northern Italy?
From a tree
that I felled myself?
Or do we actually
have a pasta machine?
I have a pasta machine.
Pasta is done.
Make it happen, cap'n.
Hot oil, my mushrooms,
salt and pepper.
Let them get brown.
Adding some shallot, Madeira.
Watch‐a your hair‐a.
Here comes the Madeira.
I'm adding my pasta
to the water.
A little bit of the pasta water.
Crème fraîche.
Add in the pasta.
‐Got it.
‐Arugula goes on top.
A little goat cheese.
Extra virgin olive oil.
That's a dish.
♪♪♪♪
That's as good if not better
than John's charcuterie.
The goat cheese
is the perfect play.
The arugula,
the pepperiness of that,
and just that little bit
of extra crunch.
The pasta is dynamite.
The mushrooms have got
a ton of flavor.
Everything is from 15 minutes
of right here.
Only thing you have to do
is forge the fork
and make the bowl.
‐I'll work on that.
‐That's a rock‐star dish.
Nicely done.
SERVER:
Porcini noodle stroganoff.
They use that local goat cheese
that's just so delicious,
and the wonderful toss
of the arugula on top
just gives it that texture
that you're yearning for.
MAN:
The mushrooms ‐‐ it gives you
that little bit of succulentness
that goes with pasta so well.
This is Guy and Judy Davis.
Guy is our wine maker.
How long have we known
each other now?
Seven, eight?
‐Seven, eight years?
‐Yeah.
The wine country
offers so much ‐‐
tons of farm‐to‐table
attitude and energy.
How do you think
Duskie and John embody that?
JUDY: Well, every ingredient
in their dishes is a star,
and then they take it and
they make this magic with it.
Good. That's all we need.
Nothing from you, Guy. Thanks.
‐Bombolini!
‐This place is very special.
Everything that goes onto
your plate is heartfelt.
FIERI: You got to come check out
Zazu and meet these two.
It'll be worth your time.
Adios. Well done.
‐Ciao. Thank you.
‐Nice.
Ciao. Buh‐bye now!
See you later!
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Up next, a funky joint
in San Antonio...
[ Mumbling with mouth full ]
...hitting it
out of the park...
Impressive.
...with their
Chicago specialties.
You are the real deal.
♪♪♪♪
I'm here in San Antonio, Texas,
right off the Loop 410,
and I love coming down here.
I mean, the people are great,
the food's awesome,
and if you're looking
for iconic Chicago food,
you got ‐‐
Wait a second.
Iconic Chicago food
in San Antonio?
Oh, yeah.
I hear this guy's the real deal.
This is Wrigleyville Grill.
MAN:
Maxwell Street Polish up.
Wrigleyville knocks the ball
out of the park.
‐Hot peppers!
‐It's absolutely legit.
I feel like I'm in Chicago
every time I come in.
FIERI: That's exactly
how Demetrios Tingas,
better known as Jimmy,
likes it.
I'm a Chicagoan.
41 years in Chicago.
Right.
And when he moved south
and missed his hometown staples,
well,
he just made them himself.
Italian beef,
hot and wet, up!
The beef is tender, juicy.
You order it wet, or dipped,
as a true Chicagoan would.
This, I hear,
is the real deal.
This is it ‐‐
the famous Italian beef.
So we're gonna
braise this.
These are the drippings
from yesterday's beef.
Okay.
We're gonna put the bay leaves,
granulated garlic.
Black pepper.
The oregano.
A little fennel, and last
but not least, kosher salt.
Now, what temp,
and how long in the oven?
350 degrees for about
3 1/2 hours.
How long
will that last you?
Maybe lunch.
One day?
Yeah.
This one's a big one.
I got you.
You got‐‐ [ Laughs ]
Whoa!
So now for the jus.
This is the liquid gold
right here.
All the drippings, beef base,
bay leaves, granulated garlic.
Oregano, basil,
black pepper, and chili flake.
Add some more water.
And how long
is that gonna cook?
Overnight.
Take it and strain it.
And then take that beef, dip it,
warm it, and serve it.
Correct.
We're cutting the ends
off the bun.
Right.
So when we dunk it,
we get the juice inside there.
Oh, I gotcha. You didn't ask me
if I wanted it wet or not.
In Chicago, you got
to have it wet.
If you want it dry,
you're from San Antonio.
Ohh!
And the giardiniera
is imported?
That's from Chicago.
FIERI: Pickles ‐‐ you got
olives, you got carrots,
you got cauliflower,
you got red chili flake,
got a little onion...
That's it.
♪♪♪♪
[ Chuckles ]
Is it okay?
That's as close as it is
to the original.
The key is to get it dipped but
not have it so submerged that,
when you pick it up,
it falls apart.
But this right here,
when it's just nice and tender
on the inside and just
a little soggy on the outside...
Mmm.
I can't get it in my mouth
fast enough.
Would help if you pushed it
with a...
You sure know
what you're doing.
And that's a lot cheaper
than a plane ticket
to fly to Chicago.
You got that right.
Mmm.
Two Italian beef,
hot and wet.
Sliced thin, scrumptious,
with all the fixings on it.
How close to legit Chicago food
is this?
I have come to love this
far better than in Chicago.
Shh! You're gonna get us
both run out.
You're never gonna go back
to Chicago, and nor will I.
I mean, we're safe here.
FIERI: And with a name
like Wrigleyville,
you can guess which home
team is in the house.
Game day?
Cubs games.
This is about as much
of a clubhouse
for transplants
as there is.
Everybody's here watching
the game, eating his food.
Bacon burger with cheese
coming up!
San Antonio's kind of known
for hamburgers,
but I'll tell you,
the place I always come
for a burger is right here.
And then this is the only place
where you can get
a really good chili cheese fry.
All right, Chef.
So what do we got?
TINGAS: We're going ground
beef ‐‐ shoulder clod, 80/20.
That's a lot of clod.
So we're gonna make
a wet rub.
Cumin, onion.
Black pepper.
Granulated garlic!
Granula‐‐
How'd you know that?
Oh, 'cause...
just the way you were
winding up for it.
Seasoned salt?
That's exactly what it is.
And Worcestershire?
Worcestershire sauce.
And this looks like steak
sauce to me.
It is.
Love me some steak sauce.
A little bit of water?
Of course.
How long is this
gonna marinate?
Two, three hours.
Two, "tree."
Then grind it.
You grind
all your own meat?
Yes.
Impressive.
What are we into now?
We're making the chili.
Ground beef, the onion.
The jalapeño.
Jalapeños.
I'm helping.
Cumin, garlic, paprika.
Chili powder, brown sugar.
Did you announce
at the Cubs?
Brown sugar!
And salt.
Aw!
Crushed tomatoes,
ground tomatoes, pinto beans.
You want to puree half of them,
the other half whole.
Okay. How long is this
gonna cook down there?
A couple hours.
All right,
chili's working.
Time to make the burger.
And here we go.
We go from grilling it
to hitting it on a flat top.
All we wanted was the char marks
on the grill.
All right, Jimmy.
Put the bacon on.
Little pigs
they have here.
Grilled onions, and
then we're going to
put the cheese on there.
Just cover it up.
Here's our hand‐cut fries.
Check one of these
for scientific purposes.
Here's the chili we just made
and the cheese sauce.
Put the lettuce down,
the beef patty, tomato,
pickle, mustard, mayo.
Look at that.
When you think of chili
cheese fries,
that's the definition
right there.
A little processed cheese,
homemade chili.
♪♪♪♪
[ Mumbles indistinctly ]
I totally agree with you.
See?
Here's the deal.
If a guy's gonna
scratch‐make it all ‐‐
season, marinate,
grind the meat ‐‐
all in this great environment
with Chicago attitude?
My kind of joint.
Nicely done, brother.
Bacon burger
and chili cheese fries up!
My good friends Shawn and Haley.
They just got married.
The beef
is just really juicy,
and it has the bacon
and all of the fixings.
It just all comes together
really nicely.
Uh‐huh.
You see that?
That's how you do it, Shawn.
And these fries
are killer.
The fries are dynamite.
‐Oh, my God.
‐Chicago dog ‐‐ one, two, three.
I love Wrigleyville.
It's like
a home away from home.
FIERI: I was surprised to find,
all the way in San Antonio,
that someone
was doing Chicago food.
And I said,
"If they're doing it,
they better be
the real deal."
You are the real deal.
Thank you.
FIERI: Coming up, we're staying
in San Antonio...
Whew!
...for some
Argentinean flavor...
That's an empanada.
...savory, spicy, and sweet.
That's an adult
jelly‐filled doughnut.
This is from one of my cousins,
who's got a restaurant.
Hold on, hold on.
Why, when you got it from him,
did you give me the Elvis?
Oh, I don't know.
No?
It just came naturally.
That's just what goes on?
We're getting things
going right now.
We're warming up!
♪♪♪♪
So, I'm here on the west side
of San Antonio, Texas,
and you are gonna love
this story.
Two immigrants, husband‐and‐wife
team, from Argentina,
decided to open
an empanada restaurant.
First location, not so great.
People don't understand
empanadas, and they close.
What do they do?
They don't back down.
Nope, they open up a food truck
serving empanadas,
and they do great.
And that leads them to opening
up a new restaurant.
Oh, you're gonna love the story
and love the food.
This is Fat Tummy.
Ham and cheese,
and humita empanadas.
These are some of
the best empanadas I've had.
A traditional
with spicy sauce.
They're out of this world.
It's a way of life in Argentina.
FIERI:
But not so much in San Antonio.
What happened
to the first restaurant?
They needed to know
what an empanada was.
They wanted tacos.
FIERI: So Gustavo Plache
and Norah Saleh
took their empanadas to
the street and won folks over...
Mmm.
...which opened the door
to this place.
Why do you call it
Fat Tummy?
SALEH: 'Cause the empanadas
are kind of fat.
They're full.
They're huge.
So, we're gonna make
the savory empanada dough?
Yes.
Flour.
Water, okay,
and some salt.
Yes.
Milk.
Butter, egg.
And who taught you
this recipe?
My grandmother.
To graduate school,
you have to have
math and history
and empanada.
Empanada.
So we'll mix this.
How long
do we let it rest?
45 minutes,
and then, "Tch!"
Everybody knows what "tch"
means.
Start to sheet it out.
W‐w‐w‐wait.
That's a big empanada.
Yeah.
Not a little empanada.
No, no, no, no.
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Fat Tummy.
So what's the first empanada
we're making?
Corn and cheese, but...
Corn and cheese,
but we call it...
Humita.
It's almost like a creamed corn.
Just awesome.
This is the sofrito?
Yes.
Oil, onion.
Green and red
bell pepper.
Sofrito has such a foundation
in Latin cooking.
Salt, black pepper...
...garlic.
[ Whistles ]
And oregano?
Oregano.
How long is this
gonna cook, Chef?
Seven minutes.
Now...
Corn, the sofrito
we made, okay.
Parmesan cheese.
And mozzarella.
Yes, yes.
That's it?
FIERI:
And as long as we're at it,
why not fire up another filling?
Next we're gonna make
the spicy chicken?
The spicy chicken.
Oil, onion...
A little salt.
Paprika, garlic, basil.
Basil, okay.
Oregano.
Black pepper.
Boiled chicken breasts
that you chop up.
Yeah.
Mix.
Tomato sauce,
chipotle en adobo.
When you say spicy chicken,
you mean spicy chicken.
All right, so we let
that cook for...
20, 25 minutes.
And now what is this?
Spicy chimichurri sauce.
When I think about Argentinean
food, I don't think "spicy."
No, but the people
right here like the spicy.
so you got to bring
the spicy.
Yes.
Cilantro, garlic powder,
salt, egg.
Egg?
In chimichurri?
You try.
Okay!
Chile de árbol.
A lot of them.
Yes.
Now?
This is the craziest chimichurri
I've ever seen.
Yeah.
Whew!
It's hot.
Wow!
It's really good.
That's gonna be awesome
with the empanada.
Now, this is
a special press?
Yes.
Has your name ‐‐
Fat Tummy.
And humita.
You make a different empanada,
you put a different...
Yes, chicken,
"P" ‐‐ the pollo.
Just a little water
to seal it.
Exactly.
[ Whistles ]
Okay, one, two, three.
That's
a lot of empanada.
They're stuffed.
Let me see this thing.
[ Laughs ]
So heavy.
That's an empanada.
Now the spicy chicken?
The spicy chicken.
Egg.
Little bit of egg.
How long do they bake?
Four minutes.
There's the pollo,
and I'll try the humita first.
Look at that cheese
melting in there.
[ Harp plays ]
Like a commercial.
Mm‐hmm.
Put just a little
of the chimichurri on there.
I don't even know why I just put
that chimichurri on there.
I know how hot that is.
The dough is really good,
the filling is fantastic,
and the chimichurri
goes with it perfect.
And this is
the spicy chicken.
Spicy chicken.
Love the little glaze
on top.
Fantastic.
Look at the juice
just running out of this thing.
Not overly spicy.
For anybody that hasn't had
an empanada,
this is where
they need to start.
It doesn't get any better
than that.
I have humita,
spicy chicken.
The spicy chicken is excellent,
just hits the right spot.
The humita empanada
has lots of cheese.
It's very creamy.
‐Chimichurri's really good.
It's very herby.
Beef and potato,
and ham and cheese, ready!
You're a food blogger here.
Yes, sir.
People in San Antonio
know good food.
Oh, yeah.
We love our eat‐local scene,
and these people fit
right in there.
They're great people.
I just enjoy them.
Chorizo and egg!
FIERI: How many different
empanadas do you make?
10.
How many are sweet?
‐Three sweet.
‐The guava empanadas.
The guava and cheese
is excellent.
WOMAN: It kind of reminds me of,
like, having fruit
and cheese for dessert.
I've had this empanada
before.
I want to see
how you make it.
A little bit smaller, and the
dough is a little bit sweeter.
Exactly.
Guava paste.
I got you.
Now the cream cheese?
Cream cheese.
And we mash it together.
And the guava paste is a little
sweet, little tang.
What he's gonna do with this
empanada is gonna be dynamite.
Love these presses.
Impressed.
Little bit of egg wash.
Yes.
We bake it five minutes?
No, this ‐‐ two minute.
A little sugar?
You think so?
Yeah.
That's my jam right there ‐‐
the savory‐sweet.
The cream cheese,
the tanginess
and the...flavor profile
of the guava paste
and the tender dough
on the outside,
with a little caramelized sugar
on top.
That's an adult jelly‐filled
doughnut.
This with some coffee?
Yeah.
Huh?
WOMAN: Here's a guava empanada
for you guys.
It's a perfect amount
of sweetness.
[ Speaking in Spanish ]
MAN: It's something about
this humble guy.
That's why the taste
is so great.
You're the example
of the American story.
Come to this country,
work really hard,
work with your family.
That's why we do "Triple D."
Great job, man.
Made me cry.
♪♪♪♪
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
And what have I told you guys
about having people on the show
with better hair than me?
Eh?
[ Laughter ]
I said, "Stop this
better hair thing."
Gosh!
I was gonna ask you...
Where's the bleach?
...if I could go
to your hairdresser.
Oh, you're killing it, girl.
[ Laughs ]