You know, folks ask me
all the time, "Hey, Guy.
That place you went to
in that one town
that served that one dish,
how are they doing
after 'Triple D'?"
You know what? I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip,
we're spinning the globe...
Whoa, whoa,
whoa-whoa, whoa-whoa.
...and taking Flavortown
international.
In Salt Lake City,
this Vietnamese sandwich shop
is just killing the kimchi.
You know what I have
to say about that?
ALL: Oh Mai!
[ Laughs ]
A taco spot in San Antonio
has got me all tongue-tied.
That's what I'm talking about.
Ohh!
And in Glendale, Arizona...
That's killer.
...break out the lederhosen
'cause this German joint's
still bringing down the house.
Come see my twin.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Salt Lake City.
Last time I was here,
it was like 2014,
and I stumbled upon this funky
little Vietnamese sandwich shop.
Well, they had two locations
at the time.
I cruise back into town
five years later,
and I hear that they've got
six locations?
You know what I said?
Oh Mai.
♪♪
I always come here whenever
I feel like having something
that's really tasty
and really quick.
The thing I like about Oh Mai
is all the unique flavors.
The pho is always great
in the winter when it's cold.
FIERI:
Owners Long and Anna Tran
should be kicking back
and playing golf.
ANNA: We finally
decided to retire,
so that's why we bought
this little place.
You retired and did this?
[ Laughs ] Yes.
We have to have a talk.
I said I was stepping by
to check on things
and how we were doing,
and I was on the way
down to the old one.
You told me that was, like,
your retirement deal.
What happened?
The show aired.
That's what happened.
-Oh, so it's my fault?
-[ Laughs ] Yeah.
So, when I came there,
I brought my buddy Jimmy John.
-He is like a...
-A sandwich god.
He's like
a sandwich god, yes.
So you know Jimmy Johns?
Yes.
Okay, so, let's talk about
what we're gonna make.
What kind of sandwich?
We're making the garlic
ribeye bánh mí today.
-Garlic ribeye bánh mí?
-Yes.
Everything sound good
to you so far?
Sounds good.
I'm just gonna qualify
everything through Jimmy
since he's, like, you know,
the sandwich pro here.
Put in the butter.
And then onions and garlic.
This is the ribeye
that goes in the sandwich?
-Correct.
-Beautiful.
Soy sauce. Sugar.
And then black pepper.
Okay. Now we're ready
to go make a sandwich?
So, what I do
is cut it out.
-With scissors?
-Yes. [ Laughs ]
-And then we hollow this out.
-We call it "canoeing."
Just the garlic butter, mayo,
and then Romaine lettuce.
And then...
The black vinaigrette?
House sauce. Black pepper.
Cucumber.
[ Whistles ]
-Tomato.
-That looks good.
Red onion.
Oh, I like
the jalapeño.
Carrots and daikon.
And cilantro.
It's an Asian
Philly steak.
It is an Asian
♪♪
And that's all she wrote.
Here we go.
That is unbelievable.
Whoa, whoa,
whoa-whoa, whoa-whoa.
ANNA: When people come
over here to visit,
they just sit, look at the menu,
and they say,
"I want what Guy want."
FIERI: The "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives" Delight.
The quadruple D.
[ Laughs ]
You know what I have
to say about that? Oh Mai.
All right, so, what are
the new heavy hitters?
This is the short-rib
kimchi sandwich.
Short-rib kimchi.
-Yes.
-Are you making the kimchi?
Yes.
We made it in house.
First, we're gonna put in
some chopped napa cabbage.
We'll have some vinegar.
And then minced ginger.
Minced garlic,
chili powder, Sriracha.
And Korean chili powder.
And some sugar.
So a little bit more sweet
versus the Korean version.
And then we're gonna
marinate it all together,
and then we'll put it in the
fridge for about two days.
We have some chuck roast,
sliced thinly.
We're gonna put in some
Korean barbecue sauce,
minced garlic, vegetable oil,
baking soda, and black pepper.
We're gonna marinate it
about 15 minutes,
and we can just wait
for it to be seared.
And then next,
I would add onion, scallion,
sliced cucumber,
kimchi, cilantro,
jalapeño pepper, black pepper,
then the hot chili sauce.
♪♪
FIERI: Delicious.
There's such a difference
between house-made kimchi
and processed kimchi.
SO anytime
you make your own,
you get a completely
different flavor.
The baguette,
the size of the sandwich.
You guys got all ridiculous.
That's crazy.
We've got a spicy beef
short rib.
MAN:
The kimchi is very sweet.
The meat is nice and tender,
very flavorful.
It's just the unique ingredients
layered on top of each other.
The flavors meld together,
but there's definitely
an underlying kick.
We had such a blast
that day when we came
here and had the pho.
Spelled "P-H-O" with an accent
over the top of it.
-Uh-huh.
-But it is pronounced "FA."
-Yes.
-Now, I'm a pho junkie.
I mean, I can pho it up.
So don't pho-get it.
-Don't pho-get it.
-Sorry. I had to.
So we're gonna cook off
the beef bones first.
Mm-hmm.
Next, we're gonna put
the brisket into the pot.
This will cook
for about three hours.
While that is being cooked,
then we can start
roasting the spices.
-A little cinnamon?
-Cinnamon.
Star anise.
-Amomum.
-Amomum?
-Yes.
-How do you pronounce it?
Wrong every time.
So we're gonna toast these
about five minutes.
You take out
the cooked brisket.
Now we add the spice in.
Yes.
Look at that.
[ Whistles ]
And how long are we gonna
steep that in there?
For about six more hours.
With that in there?
-Yes.
-Wow.
And then we're
gonna put this in.
So we've got the
roasted ginger and onions.
-I like this.
-And then...
Crystallized rock sugar
and a little bit of salt.
And salt. Yep.
Then you just
pour the noodle in.
So, that rice noodle
went really fast.
And then you put in the brisket,
put in the broth.
Then you just garnish it
with green onions,
cilantro, and red onions.
And last, but not least,
the black pepper.
♪♪
I wish I could get in it.
I want to be in the bowl.
♪♪
Mmm!
-You really like that?
-It's phenomenal.
Okay. I thought
he was just acting.
In my world of pho,
this is one of the best.
Acting?
Do I look like an actor?
I know that afterward
that you're not.
Huh. I'll show you
acting right now.
[ Dramatically ]
I'll tell you what.
[ Laughter ]
When we come back,
we are going to make...
The honey-glazed pork
vermicelli noodle salad.
It's easy for her to say.
Next stop, food coma.
You call this a salad?
Oh, we're back?
Welcome back to Oh Mai.
I just had an
un-pho-gettable experience.
Mmm! We just made pho
that was out of bounds.
I want to be in the bowl.
FIERI: The first time
I was there, Anna and Long
were running a couple small
joints outside Salt Lake City.
How many of these
do you have now?
-We have six now.
-And two on the way.
You know what I have
to say about that?
ALL: Oh Mai!
[ Laughter ]
The "Oh Mai" choir.
FIERI: The name was inspired
by Anna's mom, Mai,
and so were some
of the recipes.
What am I having?
ANNA: The honey-glazed pork
vermicelli noodle salad.
FIERI: Which includes a marinade
I had a hand in making.
-You can hold onto that for me.
-Thank you very --
That's about all I'm
capable of at this point.
Okay. We put in
some green onion tips.
White onion.
And fresh shallots.
There we go.
Okay. We good?
We're -- We're good.
Okay, and then you
just pour it in here.
Then next you put in
some sugar.
Black pepper.
Fish sauce.
Some honey.
-That's the honey glaze?
-Yes.
Of all this honey talk
I've heard, that's it?
It gives it color. Yeah.
Then you just mix it up.
-How long will this marinate?
-I will say eight hours.
-Eight hours?
-Yes.
Put it on the heat.
And this was
the pork butt?
Pork shoulder?
Pork sirloin.
Perk -- Pork sore-lo--
Sur-lo-- Pork sore-loin.
Port -- Pork --
Pork sore-loi--
You know what it is.
So, now we're gonna
start to assemble
the glazed pork
noodle salad.
I'll put some lettuce in,
some bean sprouts.
And then I'll put a bed of
noodle. You serve them chilled.
Some cucumber.
Pickled carrots and daikon.
And then the pork.
And some onion scallion.
And then black pepper
and some shallot to give it
a little crunch.
And then finally chili-lime
fish vinaigrette,
which is fish sauce,
vinegar, lime pulp,
water, sugar,
and sambal chili.
Just pour it on top,
and you just mix it up,
and it's ready to serve.
-Very fresh.
-You call this a salad?
Yeah. Noodle salad.
♪♪
I'm having a salad, though.
So slimming.
Delicious.
MAN: The vinaigrette really
makes the vegetables pop,
and the lime goes
really well with the meat.
MAN:
It's a great combination
of warm meat
and then the cool noodles,
and then the vegetables
and all the other flavors.
Congratulations.
Very happy for you.
You deserve it.
You deserve it tenfold.
Thank you so much.
Okay? Keep it up,
and I bet, oh, next time
I come back in five years,
we'll just change the city to...
ALL:
Oh Mai, Salt Lake City.
That's what I said.
♪♪
I can't wait to see it
on the map --
Oh Mai, Salt Lake City.
I mean, next thing we know,
they're gonna be
taking over the entire state.
Now, coming up,
we're checking in
on Triple D's
very first German joint.
I'll be having
the schnitzel.
And it might just
have you seeing double.
But Mom always liked you
better anyway.
♪♪
On "Triple D,"
I'm always searching
for the real-deal joints,
and in Glendale, Arizona,
I found a spot so legit,
you should have a passport
just to get in the front door.
[ Tuba playing ]
And not to mention it was kind
of like looking in a mirror.
A big mirror.
This is Haus Murphys.
♪♪
WOMAN: It's like
a real German beer hall.
The servers and waitresses
are in their German attire.
I've never really had
anything here I didn't enjoy.
MAN: I like how they present it.
I like what's in it.
The whole flavor
all around works.
FIERI: And it's all thanks
to this dude, Brett Hoffman,
who happens to be my,
well, how do you say it
in German?
Doppelganger?
Okay.
Let's just --
HOFFMAN: We looked at each
other, and it was like, "Hmm."
I said, "One of us is adopted."
This is actually
my twin brother,
and this is why you shouldn't
put hormones in milk.
FIERI: He may look like a Fieri,
but he's not cooking up Italian.
He's whipping up German classics
he learned from his grandparents
and wife, Rose.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu that you make?
-Sauerbraten.
-"Sauer" is "sour."
And "braten" means...
Roast.
We're making a sour roast?
-Yeah.
-Mmm!
We're gonna trim it.
We're gonna cut it down.
We were the first German
restaurant on "Triple D,"
and I thought it was pretty cool
that we were the first.
Now we're gonna add our liquid.
Some vinegar.
-Okay, a little buttermilk.
-Little buttermilk.
So that's the sour part.
Onion, carrots, celery.
-Okay.
-Yeah.
-Whole peppercorn.
-Bay leaf.
Clove. Nutmeg.
-Little bit of salt.
-Just a touch.
And white pepper.
Mix this all up.
Now, how long is this
gonna marinate?
This is gonna marinate
at least four to five days.
-Days?
-Days.
We're adding the oil
to our pot.
We're gonna throw
our onions in.
Let that cook for
a couple minutes.
Then we're gonna add
our lovely, lovely meat.
Now we're gonna add
some red wine and deglaze
that a little bit.
Then we're gonna add
our marinades.
So, the marinade
that we had for five days.
Yep. Yep.
Welcome to another edition --
"As the Sauer Bratens."
FIERI: And, so,
this is a delicacy.
I mean, this is
really something
that when people come out
for German food at Haus Murphys
that they're
really excited to have.
-Yeah, they are.
-As hard as it takes to make it.
Exactly. Nobody wants
to do this at home.
♪♪
-Mm-hmm.
-That is great.
-It's not too tender.
-Mnh-mnh.
It's not too tough.
But there is a contrast.
-It's sweet...
-And sour.
This food is way better than my
mom's. It's a secret, though.
-Shh.
-Don't tell her.
All 40 million of you,
don't say a word.
FIERI: But this isn't the only
low-and-slow beef dish
he's bringing to the table.
He's also rolling out
this one -- the beef rouladen.
Little hard to make.
It's time-consuming.
Beef rouladen.
It's also one of the best
sellers in the restaurant.
This is my seasoning that I use.
Mixture of white pepper,
seasoned salt,
and brown mustard.
Make sure that we get
a nice, good coating on that.
Now we do the onion, pickle.
And then our bacon.
Now we're going to roll this up.
We sear them on the flat top,
get them brown
all the way around.
When they're done,
we put those in an au-jus bath.
We warm those up.
We put those on a plate.
We put our gravy.
We serve that with spaetzle
and red cabbage.
WOMAN: The meat is so tender.
It's juicy.
I love the gravy on top.
It's so tender that you
really don't even need
the knife to cut it with.
So, I am concerned that next
time I go out looking for this,
I'm gonna have to
interview them.
"How many days?
What kind of vinegar?
Do you measure
your brown sugar?
Ah, ha, ha.
I thought not.
I'll be having
the schnitzel."
Mmm.
That's nice.
I've had schnitzel.
But not like that.
I've never had like that.
That's got some killer crunch.
Oh, the sauce is money.
That paprika
changes it all.
BRETT: The sauerbraten
and the paprika schnitzel
are still on the menu,
and they're huge sellers.
Can't make enough of it
sometimes on a weekend.
Those are staples I'll never
be able to get rid of.
FIERI: And since they're
dedicated to keeping it real,
what better place to dig up new
recipes than Grandma's cookbook?
MAN: Oma's hackbraten.
Oma's hackbraten.
It's like German meatloaf.
The first thing we start with
is a little celery salt,
granulated onion,
caraway seed, parsley...
marjoram, white pepper...
fresh garlic, curry...
Worcestershire...
beef concentrate, our eggs.
And now, last but not least,
panko breadcrumbs.
There we go.
Now the fun part.
This is how Grandma did it.
I'm not gonna argue
with my grandmother.
Now our bacon.
This gives it
just more good flavor.
We're ready for ketchup.
This helps brown the top,
make it nice and crusty.
And we are gonna bake this
for about two hours.
Pour our gravy on top of that,
and we serve it
with German potato salad.
FIERI: And that potato salad
had me going.
That's killer.
When he was here,
he just kept eating it
and eating it and eating it.
Okay, so, now we're gonna dump
our freshly cooked potatoes.
Bacon, sautéed onions,
some white pepper...
granulated garlic,
caraway seed...
fresh garlic, parsley,
chicken stock.
And there we have
German potato salad.
♪♪
WOMAN: Hackbraten
is the German meatloaf.
The seasoning that goes in there
is amazing.
WOMAN: German potato salad
is really, really good.
As far as texture,
it's not overpowering.
It's very flavorful.
You know what?
You're not the boss.
Yeah, well, Mom always
liked you better anyway.
[ Laughs ]
Come see my twin.
[ Laughter ]
Well, some things do change.
Since one of us got a haircut,
there shouldn't be
any more confusion.
Now, coming up,
a place you won't have
any trouble figuring out...
That's what
I'm talking about. Ohh!
...because it's all
in the name.
It's so nice,
they named it twice.
FIERI:
In San Antonio, Texas,
I checked out this taco joint
with the Greek owner,
whose food was so good, she even
convinced me to try the lengua.
That's right. Cow tongue.
Please help me, please help me,
please help me, please help me.
But, hey, they figured out what
works, and are sticking to it.
This is Taco Taco Cafe.
♪♪
We saw this place on "Triple D."
This is exactly the kind of
place that you're gonna see.
This mom-and-pop. Great food.
Makes you want
to keep coming back.
WOMAN:
From the working person
to someone who just woke up
and wants a taco,
it's very welcoming to all.
FIERI: That's thanks
to owner Helen Velesiotis.
There's no person in the world
like Helen Velesiotis.
She is just amazing.
-Aww! [ Laughs ]
-I love you.
FIERI: And when everybody stops
by, they feel the love, too.
I gave him a kiss right there
on the cheek.
You make almost
everything yourself?
Everything myself.
Everything handmade.
We need two egg tacos.
How many flour tortillas
do you make in a day?
1,000 to 2,000 tortillas
a day.
He's all,
"How about this lady?"
-Each one by hand?
-Each one by hand.
FIERI: Look at that.
We've already made two,
and I'm tired.
That's what
I'm talkin' about.
Ohh! Ohh!
That tortilla is legit,
but what Helen wanted me
to put in it...
You're gonna love lengua.
I have not had much tongue
that I've liked.
I make lengua.
It was something
he was afraid to try.
Why do I do this
to myself?
You boil them,
then they cool.
Now, you skin the tongue?
-Yes.
-Oh...look at that.
It's like
mouth roast beef.
Start cutting into cubes.
Now we're gonna...
Sautée.
-Gonna put a little oil.
-Okay.
Gonna shovel
in the lengua.
Yes.
This just puts
a whole new definition
on finger-lickin' good,
doesn't it?
Yes.
We're gonna brown it
a little bit.
-Onions?
-Tomatoes.
-Jalapeños.
-That's a lot of jalapeños.
You don't even feel the heat.
The lengua takes it away.
It just licks the flame.
Yes. Of course.
Tomato sauce.
You stir it.
I pray that
it breaks down more,
'cause there's big chunks...
of tongue.
FIERI:
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is straight-up, downtown,
in-your-face lengua.
And because you made it,
I'm goin' after it.
Well...
What do you think?
This is cooked so well,
you might have converted me
to lengua forever now.
It's a real rich flavor
to it.
That's dynamite.
She's a superstar.
But she's not just stuffin'
those tacos with tongue.
She's also putting
a little shoulder into it,
as in carne guisada.
HELEN:
We take our beef shoulder,
and we boil it about two hours,
and when it's become tender,
we go ahead
and put some spices in it,
some salt, some chili blend.
And then we make separate roux
with oil, flour.
And we put it in slowly,
and it brings out
the flavor of the meat.
The consistency needs to be
thick but easy to scoop out.
♪♪
MAN:
It's really, really good.
It's got a really
creamy texture.
The meat just falls apart.
WOMAN: Very tender meat.
It was very simple,
but it was just delicious.
You know what you
should name this place?
-Taco Taco Cafe.
-That's a great name.
It's so nice,
they named it twice.
I haven't changed
the menu.
The prices are the same
as Guy Fieri was here.
Why should I make any change?
Things have gone great.
-You want you back.
-I'll be back.
Let's make a plan.
SERVER:
Carne guisada plate.
You're back.
Thank you for coming.
♪♪
You are so welcome.
Listen, there's nothing
I like better than checking in
on Triple D chefs taking the
opportunity and running with it.
Like Anna and Long,
whose Vietnamese sandwich shop
in Salt Lake City
has taken the town by storm.
And my brother
from another mother --
Brett's German joint keepin' it
uber-authentic in Arizona.
And, of course,
Helen in San Antonio,
whose customers are loving
her "not changing a thing"
mentality.
Listen, we'll catch up
with more faces and places
next time on "Triple D Nation."
Like this.
Jazz hands!
[ Laughs ]
-Jazz hands!
I'm telling you, jazz hands
is gonna make it.
[ Laughter ]