I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're going round two
revisiting some of our favorite
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This is "Triple D Nation."
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning...
[ Both laugh ]
...'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up...
Did you see that?!
...and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
In Post Falls, Idaho...
Is your mouth watering?
...an Italian pub slinging pie
as legit as the name...
A name like "Capone,"
it better be.
...a spot in Nashville
going hog wild...
Holy hog!
Oh, my gosh.
...opening barbecue joints
all over town.
And an eclectic eatery...
Aren't you gonna make
any for yourself?
...classing up
comfort food.
I have to jog back to California
to lose some of this.
Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors...
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, I'm on a big family
road trip.
We're on our way
to Yellowstone,
and we're cruising
along Interstate 90
going to Coeur d'Alene, Idaho,
to check out a joint
that we shot about 8 years ago
on "Triple D."
And all of a sudden
I see this big billboard.
I said, "Wait a second!"
They've got another location
in Post Falls?
I've got to check it out.
This is Capone's.
♪♪
MAN: It's like a pub
mixed with a sports bar,
but Capone's just
does it tenfold.
Boneless chicken wings.
MAN #2: It's the food
that brings me in first,
and then,
it's the atmosphere.
Looks better than ever.
I did see this place
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
so, we decided
to come here.
It's one of our favorites.
I talk to people all the time
when I come here.
They've seen it
on "Triple D,"
and it's great recognition
for Tom.
FIERI: That would be
Chef Tom Capone
and his wife, Teresa,
who own the joint.
And when I first
checked this place out,
I knew they were
the real deal.
And your last name
is really Capone?
It is.
Seriously?
-Serious.
-Where'd you learn to cook?
My Irish aunt
taught my Sicilian dad
how to cook Italian food,
and he taught me.
Guy and I,
we have a common bond.
We're both
Italian and Irish.
Roasted garlic
chicken pizza.
All right, so, let's go.
What are we making first?
All right. We're gonna
make some pizza dough.
Look at the guns, yeah.
Yeah, he's got
the guns.
Flour, active dry yeast.
Salt. Brown sugar.
You've got a ton
of brown sugar in there,
and you think that's
gonna be okay?
TOM:
He asked me why we put brown
sugar instead of white sugar.
We just found that we get
a better rise out of our dough.
Adds, like, a little
different taste.
-I love it.
-We use a garlic- infused oil.
Smell this.
It's not even cooking,
and I'm juicing up.
The jowls
are sweating.
FIERI: He also rocked
a homemade no-cook pizza sauce.
You should have
some safety goggles on!
Tomato sauce we made.
This is a whole-milk mozzarella.
Artichoke hearts,
roasted garlic,
Kalamata olives,
and sundried tomatoes.
It's gonna be a good pie,
you say.
I hope so.
Name like Capone, it...
BOTH: Better be.
Cut it up.
We're gonna top the pizza
with the chicken.
Is your mouth watering?
That's the
roasted garlic chicken pizza.
Mmm!
That's a hot deck.
And that's great dough.
It's kind of like
putting the icing on top.
Garlic chicken --
the new icing in Flavortown.
TOM: The roasted garlic
chicken pizza
has gone crazy
since he was here.
It's probably
our largest seller.
Right up there, yep.
I don't know.
Personally, I think
the burgers are the best.
FIERI:
She's talking about the ultimate
burger served on a homemade bun.
This does the work for you?
-Sure does.
-Nice!
I've got to get
one of these.
Burger on the grill,
a little bit of Tom salt
Now, give it a flip.
This is beer.
Beer?
Steam the burger in beer.
Now, the cheese.
This is the super mix?
The mozz, the jack,
Pecorino, and Romano,
cheddar with
a little provolone.
Mmm! Dude, that bun
is off the hook.
If you're gonna eat a burger,
you should eat it
at a place
that makes their own bun.
The Ultimate Cheeseburger.
TOM: We had a lady,
flew in from Miami.
She had the Cheeseburger,
loved it, turned around,
flew back to Miami.
This is the right size mixer
for a job like this.
[ Imitates mixer
whirring ]
I know. I know.
But you got to understand --
I only got one stripe-y
rosy shirt to wear today.
♪♪
What's up, buddy?
How are you, brother?
Good to see you, man.
-How are you?
-You guys are busy.
-Yeah.
-Still making your own buns?
-Oh, yeah.
Still putting brown sugar
in the pizza dough?
-Yep.
-I love it.
I mean, the one
in Coeur d'Alene,
it just had
the feeling --
on the corner, right there,
small, little town.
This here, I'm driving by,
I saw a billboard
the size of my RV,
and I'm thinking, "Oh, boy,
they've gone big time.
It's not gonna be this cool,
quaint, little bar
that everybody
wants to hang out.
It totally is.
It's the same thing.
And the other one's still
going in Coeur d'Alene?
Yeah.
And we have another one.
We have a third one,
now, also.
There's another one?
Yeah.
-The house that Guy built --
-That's it.
I'm done.
Goodbye.
Nice seeing you guys.
FIERI: More locations
means more Home Run Pizza.
And when we come back...
HUNTER:
You butchered this.
FIERI: ...I'm getting Hunter
into the game,
digging into their latest
international sensation.
That's got it going on,
right there.
So, I'm in
Post Falls, Idaho,
at Capone's where the pizza's
got as big a rep as the name.
That's real deal.
Try a bite of that.
So, 2010, I checked out
their place in Coeur d'Alene.
I've always heard about
Coeur d'Alene, Idaho,
and its beautiful lake
and now, I'm finally here
to check out
a mom-and-pop pizza joint
with a real-deal Italian name
and the cooking to back it up.
So, when the annual
Fieri family road trip
took us through Post Falls
on our way to Yellowstone,
well, I had to pop in
for a little reminiscing.
TERESA: Do you remember
the half booth --
Yeah. The weird little
half booth.
Well, this is peach
of a seat, huh?
-When he got there...
-He was...
he didn't know
how to sit.
You guys
come here often?
So, of course,
everybody starts laughing.
[ Laughs ]
What is it about this place?
The table?
[ Laughter ]
Do you have
a half booth here?
-No.
-No?
There's no half booth?
What they do have
is a multi-national pie
I can't wait to try --
the Taco Pizza.
Taco Pizza.
FIERI: It all starts with
their homemade salsa.
TOM: Diced tomatoes
and puree green peppers,
jalapeño peppers, onion,
lemon juice, garlic, cumin.
The salsa is
my mom's recipe,
and she's from Texas,
so it's got a nice little kick.
It's not for
the weak at heart.
We're gonna put
our salsa pizza sauce --
whole-milk mozzarella.
Then, we're gonna
throw it in the oven.
The Taco Pizza's a different
combination of flavors.
We just wanted to come up with
something that nobody else does.
FIERI: Like pizza on the bottom,
but a fiesta on top.
Lettuce first, fresh tomatoes,
tortilla shells,
some more cheese,
fresh cilantro,
and a little bit
of jalapeño.
The last thing to on
is our fresh ground beef, here.
And since I'm on
a family road trip,
who better to join the taste
test than my son Hunter?
Pizza's not good enough
by itself?
We're gonna put
a taco on it?
Try it.
-You've butchered this.
-I have not butchered this.
Dynamite.
HUNTER:
Now, I've butchered it.
You say "Taco Pizza,"
and I'm thinking,
"It's either gonna be a taco
that has a little pizza idea,
or it's gonna be
a pizza with a --
just a brief
representation."
But it is both.
That's got it going on,
right there.
I love it.
WOMAN: It really almost
tastes like a taco,
but the crust and the bread
makes it into a pizza,
and a really good pizza
at that.
There's a little zest to it,
a little zing to it.
If you've ever tried
the Taco Pizza,
you'll come back again
for the Taco Pizza.
What else should we try?
Sweet Hot Boneless Wings.
-You make the sauce in-house?
-Yes.
It starts with ketchup,
cider vinegar,
brown sugar
spicy brown mustard, sriracha.
To sweeten it up,
we're gonna put honey in there.
These are breasts
that have been chopped up.
Now, we're gonna
add the sauce.
It's one of the most
popular ones that we have.
How is it?
You're not gonna like them.
No?
Should I just bring it
over there?
Don't even try.
You get the vinegar --
You know you're gonna
get some heat.
It's Buffalo sweet
and sour sauce.
Yeah, right?
Yeah.
That's everything I love
about a Buffalo wing
without all the work.
MAN: The boneless chicken wings
are amazing.
The sweet hot sauce
is perfect.
It couldn't be done any better.
-It's a good sauce.
It's some good wings --
and I'm a wing guy.
Well, you guys
deserve it.
I'm gonna tell you
that you deserve it.
To be recognized by your own
peers for having good food
is the biggest accolade
you could ever get
in the restaurant
business.
It's a gift.
Gift and an honor.
I get choked up.
I am so glad that they had
the Post Falls location.
I mean, it made it
a lot easier with the RV,
and it's always great to share
the Triple D Nation
with my family
Now, coming up...
[ Laughter ]
a Nashville
barbecue joint where,
I'm telling you,
they're going while hog.
I love this guy.
FIERI:
In 2010, I stopped into this
barbecue joint in Nolensville,
Tennessee,
and what are they cooking up?
A rarity in
the barbecue world -- whole hog.
Pulled pork plate,
potato salad.
You're dragging a fry.
So, what's a guy to do
when he's got
one of the only
whole-hog games in town?
Exactly --
open five more.
This is
Martin's Bar-B-Que Joint.
We first saw Martin's
on "Triple D,"
and we've fallen
in love with it.
Everything on
the menu is great.
MAN:
They have the whole whole.
It doesn't taste like smoked
pork you get anywhere else.
There's a lot of competition
in the barbecue market,
and we try other places,
but every time
we get done we're like,
"It just doesn't
compare to Martin's."
♪♪
FIERI:
It's all thanks to this guy --
Pat Martin, whose been
smoking the barbecue world
since he opened in '06.
And when we first met,
things went off the rails fast.
Should we -- Oh, is this
how we're gonna stand?
[ Both laugh ]
MARTIN: A little fake mouse,
here? Anyway --
Let's just say
we basically supplied
our own laugh track.
It was almost like
fifth graders.
Anybody in there?
And that's about the maturity
that we both have.
FIERI:
But what wasn't funny
was his seriously legit
signature seasoning.
You've got a good amount
of salt in there,
and a good amount of seasoning,
but nothing really over spicy.
MARTIN: We're not looking
for anything but an end result
of a good bark.
-Okay.
-Now, our dry mustard.
-Yep.
Our cinnamon, white sugar,
ginger, coarse black pepper.
-I like it.
-Now, we're gonna mix this.
FIERI:
This went on everything --
brisket, chicken,
even the whole hog.
And now that he's coating
his wings with it,
well, they're flying
out the door, too.
MARTIN: We're gonna cook those
at 250 for and a half hours.
Then, we're gonna get
our Alabama White Sauce
put together,
and that is mayo, cider vinegar,
Worcestershire, minced garlic,
whisk it together.
The tanginess from the vinegar,
the acidity from that vinegar --
when it's tossed in there,
it's really awesome.
People love them.
SERVER:
Six wings, Alabama White.
MAN:
They smoke their wings,
so you got a lot
of that flavor already,
and then, you put a little bit
of their Alabama White Sauce
on it.
It's a perfect blend.
The flavor is just super
juicy -- just a crisp outside.
FIERI: But when I was there,
the hog had my full attention.
I don't know exactly
where we going with that.
I thought that was --
We're just getting out
to the sprinkle dinkle.
I understood this was
sprinkle-dinkle time.
I didn't know if we were going
left, right, front, center.
We're gonna season it.
Yeah. we're gonna rub our
rub on it -- only on the meat.
There's no sense in
getting it on the skin.
That's not gonna
do you any good.
Cooking a whole hog --
there's not a lot of people
out there that do it,
so it was fun, man.
Getting him in the pit with his
little skater shorts on
and all that stuff.
You know what
I'm talking about.
FIERI: Holy hog!
This is where
the bacon comes from.
-Whoa!
-Here's some shoulder meat.
And you load her up.
There you go.
So, how are we
gonna eat this?
We're gonna do
three sliders.
This is our
Devil's Nectar,
our hot sauce
with some habanero in it.
I want you to be very,
very careful with that for me.
Our hot sauce is hot.
I made it as hot as I could get
where it still had flavor,
and I thought it was gonna
scorch his tongue off.
It's not hot yet?
Tell me that's hot.
That's the mild.
We need to go get the hot sauce.
[ Laughter ]
My guy put the sauce
in the wrong thing.
Yeah, it was mild, so...
FIERI:
But what is hot -- Martin's.
This place blew up.
MARTIN:
We've got six locations --
five here in town,
one in Louisville.
FIERI: And the massive one
in downtown Nashville
can hold up to 500
of his closest friends.
MARTIN: When we opened up
this spot downtown,
I needed to put appetizers
on the menu.
FIERI: So, he turned to
his old friend, the whole hog,
for a new spin on nachos.
MARTIN:
My tortilla chips are cut
and fried fresh in-house.
Our nacho cheese sauce
is cheddar and jack cheese mix,
whole-hog pulled pork
on there, slaw,
then, my vinegar-based sauce,
jalapeños.
It's got balance
throughout the nachos.
MAN: When you put pulled pork
into a product like nachos,
you can't help
but come out with a winner.
WOMAN: You still get, like,
the jalapeños.
You got that kick with it,
the crunchy coleslaw.
I haven't found
anything like it before.
Oh, my gosh.
Brother, you have got
some positions on barbecue
that I just got to --
I got to tell you, I respect.
Thank you.
FIERI: But these days it's not
just all about the 'cue.
He's getting into the veggie
game with his family's
not-so-secret
Broccoli Salad recipe.
MARTIN: It was my mom's recipe,
and it has quickly become
one of our top-three sides
we've got.
The dressing
is real easy --
mayo, sugar, side of vinegar,
mix it up --
kind of small-head broccoli,
sundried cranberries,
green onions, pecans.
FIERI: But what makes this
a Martin's signature salad?
MARTIN: You got some bacon,
you got some shredded cheddar.
They bring the smokiness,
just like they do with the meat,
into the broccoli, and you
combine that with the bacon --
It adds a great
deal of flavor.
WOMAN #2: It takes broccoli
to the next level,
and throws a little
Southern twist in it.
MARTIN: What it did for the
business -- It was great.
But I have never forgotten how
much fun we had goofing around.
I love this guy.
[ Laughter ]
Wow.
Where has this day gone?
Now, who knew that whole-hog
barbecue could be so funny?
Coming up...
That's a lot of ox
in a box.
...a joint in Miami
putting a whole new spin
on motel dining.
Mmm!
Think they'll rent me a room?
FIERI: So, back in 2014,
about 10 minutes
outside of South Beach, Miami,
I found this funky spot cranking
out high-class comfort food
inside of a soon-to-be
remodeled Art Deco motel.
Now, the building's
had a facelift since,
but the food's
as legit as ever.
This is Blue Collar.
Oxtail on 1.
Guy was 100% right
about Blue Collar.
The menu definitely has
something for everybody.
It's kind of a staple
in South Florida now.
Oh, my God,
that's a good-looking ragout.
MAN: I heard that it was
on the show,
so I had to come
and try it out for myself.
Ever since then,
we've been hooked.
Danny is the same guy
he was four years ago.
He's never lost his heart
or his passion for food.
FIERI: That would be
Chef Daniel Serfer,
who looked at this place
and thought,
"Braised spicy oxtail?"
When I pulled into
this parking lot, I thought,
"Mm.
You know what?
That probably over there --
They got good, spicy oxtail.
Oxtail on 1.
'Cause that's a lot of ox
in a box.
A lot of people would come in
and be like,
"Dan, how come
you're not on that show?
You fit the mold so well.
Aren't you gonna make
any for yourself?
It felt good that
we were gonna be picked --
finally.
♪♪
You've got some nice
rendering fat down in there.
Boatloads of garlic.
Celery.
Mango.
-Mango?
It kind of tempers
the heat a little.
Hit it with wine, and then,
just dump them back in.
I was really anxious.
I wanted to do it right,
and make sure it came out okay.
A couple dollops
of our mashed potatoes.
-"Dollops."
-The oxtail --
If it's not tender enough,
it's not gonna eat well.
You've got massive flavor,
but with that
little bit of spice
and that little bit of sweet
that you get on there -- dude.
Mmm.
Think they'll
rent me a room?
So, the oxtail,
even though it's a special,
we do have it pretty much
almost once a week.
We do at least
100 pounds at a time
because it's very popular.
-Killer, man.
-Thanks.
-Excellent job, Chef.
That is some
awesome oxtail.
The day where they're serving
the oxtail, people know.
They want it.
They come.
FIERI: But something
you can find every day?
The monster
five-meat mess
of cheesy delicious-ness called
"The Big Ragout."
You look like you could
have been The Big Ragout.
The Big Ragout sounds like
an appropriate kind of nickname.
Locally made sausage.
-Pancetta?
-Yep.
This is some
veal shoulder.
All kinds of flavor
down in that pan.
-Whole garlic.
-That's the way to do it.
Tomato?
-Yep.
I love where
this is going.
Now, we're gonna start adding
everything else back in.
Brisket.
-Same thing with
the pork shoulder?
-Yep.
Tell me that's
corn-starch slurry.
-It's just milk.
-Really?
I learned it from, like,
an old Italian person.
The lactose in the milk is gonna
help break down the meat,
and it's gonna help it
pull apart and shred up.
I'm gonna go try that
just because of that.
And it's got a nice,
little salty provolone.
That's ridiculous.
-It's way big.
How did you
think this up?
The Ragout is something I would
make for myself and my family.
We would always eat it, like,
on fettuccine or linguine,
and the next day, I would make
a sandwich like that.
♪♪
Very rich --
the awesome, awesome bread.
Look at that -- you got
little bits of sausage in there,
little bits of the veal.
I would die to have
that over pasta.
Come back for dinner.
[ Laughs ]
The Big Ragout is everything
the name says it is.
I have to jog back to California
to lose some of this.
The day after it aired,
we sold out of that sandwich in,
like, the first
half hour of service.
I dropped the ball. So,
from then on, I upped the par.
FIERI:
You got that right.
Since then, he's opened
a seafood joint downtown,
and he has totally blown up
the Blue Collar menu.
The menu's constantly
evolving and getting better.
FIERI: Like, if you think
you wouldn't find
Duck Confit Quesadilla at
a motel diner, you'd be wrong.
First, we have to cure
the duck with thyme,
kosher salt,
granulated white sugar.
Take our duck legs and thighs,
give them a real good coating.
Now, these ducks are gonna go
into the refrigerator
for 24-36 hours.
We're gonna cover them in fat
and put them into an oven
at 300 degrees
for 3 hours.
We're gonna shred them
and assemble our quesadillas.
Smoked Gouda, our caramelized
onions, our duck confit.
FIERI: And what's he
swapping in for salsa?
SERFER: The jam -- just little
blueberries, sugar, lemon juice.
The sweetness of the jam kind of
brings the whole thing together.
WOMAN: It's just
nice and tender.
And it goes well with, like,
the crispy tortilla.
MAN: I'm a duck lover.
But to put it into a quesadilla
and make it into
a delicious finger food --
What more could you ask for?
Buffalo Drumsticks to 1.
FIERI:
Another fan favorite --
Chef Danny's take
on Buffalo drumsticks.
But what's the hook?
The key to the Buffalo
drumsticks is the marinade,
which is yogurt.
We really just take garlic
powder, onion powder, paprika,
salt, and pepper, and cumin,
combine that with the yogurt,
let the drumsticks sit
for 18 or so hours.
And then, drop them
in the fryer,
and then, just toss them
in hot sauce and butter.
WOMAN #2: The Buffalo drumsticks
are so good,
and they are so
spiced correctly.
They're crisp.
it's not overwhelming hot,
the sauce.
It's just perfect.
I could eat them all day.
MAN #2: They're really enormous,
and they're covered
with this nice, hot glaze
and some blue cheese --
recommend 10 times
out of 10.
Well done, my friend.
Thanks.
Awesome.
So, it's places like these,
the real-deal Italian spots
with names like
"Capone's" in Idaho,
a barbecue joint
cooking up whole hogs
and taking over Nashville,
and a legit motel diner
that's keeping it real in Miami.
And that,
ladies and gentlemen,
is what makes up
the Triple D Nation.
And I can't wait to see what
other places have been up to.
I'll catch you next time
on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Thank you.
I'll be here all week.