Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Fire that missile,
soldier!
...we're showcasing
sandwiches...
[ Whistles ]
...Southern...
That's the best thing
I've ever heard.
...and South of the Border
specialties.
-Gracias.
-De nada.
We've got smoking barbecue
in Washington State.
None on my face, right?
-No, you're good.
-I'm good.
And off-the-chain chicken fest
in Montana.
It's legit, man.
And in Ashland, Oregon...
There we go.
...mega Mexican coming
straight from the heart.
All of this,
just for a tamale?
Correct.
You got the patience
of an angel.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here on West Main Street
in Bozeman, Montana,
not too far from the university.
Now, check this story out.
Husband and wife team
always comes out
to Bozeman, Montana,
for the fly-fishing --
like everybody does --
and they realize,
"Hey, there's no Southern food."
Well, if you can't find it,
then why don't you build it?
This is Roost fried chicken.
♪♪
BUCK:
Got a chicken and waffles!
All you have to say is, "Roost,"
and everybody knows that's
where to go for fried chicken.
BUCK: Chicken on a stick.
Come and get it!
FIERI: So this is kind of
what has introduced
fried chicken to the area?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
FIERI: And it took
Southern transplants to do it.
Husband-and-wife team
Joe and Susanna Darr,
along with Chef Mike Buck,
vacationed here
and loved it so much,
they put down roots
and opened
in one of Bozeman's
oldest buildings.
This is one of the first
homesteads in Bozeman,
And it was 1872.
We believe it was
a chicken coop at one time.
Boy this is some story
that's getting sold, ain't it?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
What makes
the fried chicken so great?
It's a fresh, never-frozen,
all-natural product,
pressure fried.
Whole bucket of chicken up!
We got the whole fried chicken.
It's amazing.
What are we getting into?
We're gonna make
some fried chicken.
our red rub.
We got salt,
we got pepper,
paprika and cayenne,
garlic, and onion powder.
A 3-pound chicken
broken down.
Liberally dredge it?
-Just a little bit.
We don't need that much
to go on all this.
-Let it set.
-24, 48 hours.
How is it being
the chicken professor out here?
Right? Right? [ Laughs ]
Presheatecha.
[appreciate ya]
They call me "The Chicken Man"
everywhere I go.
"Chicken Man?"
I get called "The Chicken Guy."
That's perfect.
[ Chicken clucks ]
All right, from here?
We're gonna use
a little buttermilk,
add the egg.
We're gonna dump in
our bone-in chicken.
Let it drain a little bit,
you get it nice and tacky.
While we're letting
the chicken rest,
we're going to make
our dry mix.
-Corn starch and AP flour.
-And kosher salt.
All right.
Then we put the chicken in.
And then it's going
in the fryer.
Tell me about --
why the pressure fryer?
When you seal this up,
it takes the liquid,
and it pressurizes it.
It causes the chicken
to break down faster,
so I can cook it
at a lower temperature
for less time
with less grease.
I'm a big
pressure-cooker fan.
It's really gonna break it down
and make it more tender?
-It is.
-And how fast is this gonna go?
About 13 1/2 minutes.
315 degrees.
What are we gonna eat
this with?
Collared greens!
We're gonna put some bacon in,
get it rendered,
dump in the salt,
and then put in the water.
Water and oil?
[Water popping ]
I'll be over here.
Give it a second.
Once it comes to a boil,
we're gonna add the greens.
Gonna let it simmer
for 8 to 12 hours.
You came here
for fly-fishing,
and you're making
fried chicken.
That's it.
I can just see the book title
now -- "Flying and Frying."
There we go.
Collared greens.
He's going right for it.
Oh I'm a greens junkie,
bro.
[ Laughs ]
Skin-on mash.
Butter, seasoning,
make it happen.
Those mashed potatoes
are gangster.
Thigh right on top
for you.
Add a couple pickled okra
and a biscuit.
♪♪
Delicious
with that red rub.
Yeah.
That flavor worked
its way into that chicken.
It's juicy, it's tender,
you're not fighting through
a bunch of batter.
You've got just enough
on there for the crunch.
Really tasty.
It's legit, man.
We've got the bucket.
This fried chicken is crispy,
juicy, and fabulous.
-I taste deliciousness.
-Deliciousness?
That's the best thing
I've ever heard.
FIERI: And it turns out
this Southern comfort
fits right in
with the Montana state of mind.
You're going
to Yellowstone park,
you can stop at Roost,
grab a bucket of chicken,
and head out.
Fishing, we'll come down here
and get chicken
and take it with us.
And it's always fabulous.
FIERI: Plus, it isn't
just tied to fry.
We have that rotisserie
that we put on
a couple salads and sandwiches.
Alabama Sand ready to go.
Pick it up!
The Alabama Sandwich,
it's rotisserie chicken
with white sauce on it.
Fantastic.
I get this all the time.
-What are we making?
-Our Alabama Sandwich.
Same red rub.
Let this set up
for 24, to 48?
That's it.
And how long does this
go in the rotisserie?
We're gonna cook it
for about an hour and a half.
And then we'll make
the white sauce.
Salt, sugar, put a little
fine-ground black pepper,
a little cayenne, horseradish.
Prepared horseradish.
Got it.
For a little kick.
-Apple cider vinegar.
-Apple-cider vinegar.
Mayonnaise.
That's it.
Mix it up,
let it set up overnight.
Should we, "A," say, it would
taste good on a flip-flop,
"B," say,
"That's out of bounds,"
or, "C,"
"That's off the hook"?
Go ahead.
Talk amongst yourselves.
[ Laughs ]
For everybody that said, "A,"
"That would taste great
on a flip-flop,"
you are correct.
Come down
for a free pickle.
That's it.
Rotisserie.
-That's gorgeous.
So first we're gonna
take the skin,
but we're not gonna
get rid of it.
We turn that
into the seasoning.
Going to peel off the good,
white meat.
[ Whistles ]
So we'll incorporate
white and dark into this?
Absolutely.
We're gonna cut this up.
And that skin's got
tons of flavor on it.
That's how much
is going on a sandwich?
Well, yeah.
[ Whistles ]
Any love to the bun?
We toasted it.
Okay.
Coleslaw,
Alabama white barbecue,
three pickles.
Prepare yourself.
I need a small bib.
♪♪
What's over there?
[ Laughs ]
The incorporation of the skin,
the tender chicken,
the simple rub,
but the rotisserie versus
just roasting it --
and you get the dark meat
and the white meat.
And then
the center punch,
that Alabama
white barbecue sauce.
A little acid
from the pickle,
and then a really nice bun
that's got a good toast to it.
That's everything I love
about a chicken salad sandwich
and then some.
Two Alabama Sandwiches.
Amazing seasoning.
It's just so succulent.
The white sauce has got
a little spice to it.
It's altogether
really solid.
Chick-sal, walking in.
If you're coming through
Bozeman,
you've got to come here.
I mean, this is probably
the fastest way
for me to get to the South
is to walk down the street
and come to the Roost.
Delicious.
You guys just do it right,
and you just do it honest.
If that professional
fly-fishing thing
doesn't work out
for you,
I think this cheffing
thing's going somewhere.
I mean, that's just me
going out on a limb there.
Well done.
FIERI:
Up next, a not-your-everyday
Mexican joint
in Ashland, Oregon...
She's doing something
I really like here.
...serving up tamales
with a twist...
Don't be small-e
when you get me my tamale.
And tortas loaded up
to the next level.
A torta done right
is a very special thing.
Man:
You still got some.
Other side.
♪♪
[ Beep ]
FIERI:
I'm here in the beautiful town
of Ashland, Oregon.
Oh, I've got
such great memories.
I used to come up here
when I was a kid.
My parents would come
for that Shakespeare Festival.
So you got
all this artist energy.
Well, what do you get?
You probably get
a pretty good food scene.
So if you're looking
for the artist food scene
with some Mexican flair,
it's right here.
This is Agave.
♪♪
Chilaquiles.
Man: If you're in the mood
for really quality
Latino food, Mexican food,
then this is a really nice
place for that.
I could eat here every day
and be happy.
There's a lot of passion
that goes into this restaurant.
FIERI:
And has been since '05
when Kathryn Gold
and John Hinkle
opened this joint
based on scratch-made food
and lots of love.
Unfortunately, John passed away,
so Kat recruited longtime
employee Jake Brown-VanAusdall
to help carry on the legacy.
John set the tempo,
kind of what was going on here,
and you're continuing
on this energy.
Yes.
He was quite a guy.
-Still is.
-Absolutely.
What's up, John?
What type of food is Agave?
Always fresh
and simplicity.
It's harder
to make it simple
than it is
to make it more complex.
Yes.
Man: The food is the highest
of quality.
That's the bottom-line.
Man #2:
The tacos and the tamales,
that's what I usually get
when I come in here.
Portobello and squash tamale.
I'm a tamale guy.
You can't go wrong
with this one.
The filling is just right,
and the spice is perfect.
-What are we gonna make?
-This is our red tamale sauce.
Okay.
Let's jump into it.
Anchos.
Guajillo?
California.
California, Guajillo --
pretty close.
Quartered onions and garlic,
water.
Now, how long are we gonna let
this sit here and simmer down?
They just have to rehydrate.
Gotcha.
Extra-virgin olive oil.
Oregano.
Cumin.
So bloom that,
kind of wake it up.
Put it in the pot.
Sugar, kosher salt.
Stir it a smidge.
That was a smidge, wasn't it?
-Smidge.
Puree it
with an immersion blender.
Next, I'm going to add water
with veggie base mixed in it.
Red chili sauce.
-Enchilada sauce.
So this will cook
about 10 more minutes,
and then it's ready
for the tamales.
That's delicious.
You know,
you can take that,
just warm it up, make a soup.
We do.
We actually put that
in our pozole.
Dummy.
[ Chuckles ]
I'll buy this by the gallon,
please.
Now we get into the...
Portobello
and winter squash filling.
-And what type of squash?
-Butternut.
-Very nice.
-Thank you.
Olive oil, garlic,
portobello mushrooms.
Beautiful.
And then in with the squash?
-Yes.
-Round it out, a little oregano.
Salt and pepper.
Now this is gonna simmer
down, now, for how long?
-15 minutes max.
-Just so it's tender.
Yeah, just so
it's slightly tender.
Cooked and tender.
Time for the masa.
Yes.
Vegetable shortening.
While that's creaming,
this is the masa.
-Salt.
-Baking powder.
She's doing something
I really like here.
This is water...
And vegetable stock.
...with some
vegetable stock.
The red sauce
that we made.
Pour it in here.
I mix this by hand.
I like how you're making
these little cylinders
that you're gonna
drop in there.
Yeah, just blob them in.
Little flavor bombs.
Fire that missile,
soldier!
Coordinates?
Spread the masa
on the tamale husk,
put filling in it,
roll it up,
put two olives in the top.
-And then we'll steam them.
-About an hour and a half.
All of this
just for a tamale?
Correct.
You have the patience
of an angel.
Don't be small-e
when you get me my tamale.
I'm hoping not to be.
-Cut the end off.
-Yep.
That's a big tamale.
You're looking
for the small-e tamale,
it's down the street.
What are you doing here?
Oh, we're making it
look pretty.
I'm just gonna end up
eating those.
It's good fiber.
And here's some of the red
tamale sauce we made.
It looks as if it were
a corn stalk in the field.
Well you are a child
of the '70s.
'60s.
♪♪
It's fantastic.
I wouldn't even tell people
it's vegetarian.
We don't.
The meatiness of that portobello
really carries it.
This red sauce is going
all the way through it,
but you know
what the real kicker is?
Is whipping that fat,
getting it nice and light.
And when it cooks,
it just...
Do you know
what that meant?
I do exactly.
You're pickup up
what I'm saying?
Absolutely.
When you can come
to a place like this
and get a tamale
that light and that fluffy...
Delicious.
Very simple ingredients
handled the right way,
and you get
an excellent result.
-Gracias.
-De nada.
The winter squash and portobello
tamale with rice and beans.
Blew my socks off.
They just get the ratio
with filling and masa right on.
And the blend of the squash
and the portobellos.
The sauce is delicious.
Got a real nice flavor to it.
Tamale and torta up.
You just can't beat
Mexican food here.
FIERI: And on most nights,
it's just the first act
to Ashland's legendary theater.
So we used to come up here
for the Shakespearean Festival.
-Yes.
-Which, of course,
I don't think
I appreciated as a child.
Now, I'm dying to go back
and see it.
You'll see this place clear out
at 7:30 at night
as everybody goes
to the 8:00 show.
Can they walk from here?
-Oh, absolutely.
-Okay.
FIERI: And up next,
it's the culinary encore...
What else you want to make?
-I'm making a carnitas torta.
Can we make it together?
-You can help, please.
-All right.
SERVER: Carnitas torta
with the cabbage and lime salad.
I've had a lot of tortas,
but this is the best one.
I'm gonna have to get
this more often.
FIERI:
...when we come back.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're here in Ashland, Oregon,
one of my favorite places.
I used to come here
all the time as a kid.
If I would have known that
this restaurant was gonna open,
I would have moved here.
This is Agave.
Kat and her partner
started this in 2005.
FIERI:
Then for a decade,
Kat and John built
their Mexican food cred.
And now,
even though John has passed,
the love just keeps on growing.
You can order anything here,
and you'll be happy.
GOLD: Carnitas torta.
I'm having the carnitas torta.
I order it often.
WOMAN: Super marinated meat,
jalapeños --
it's one of the best.
What are we gonna
make next?
I'm making
a carnitas torta.
We have two pork butts.
I rub them with salt.
Mexican oregano
with that big flavor.
You can smell it.
Now, I noticed that you turn
the fat cap up,
so it's gonna sit there
and render down that fat
and moisturize
the meat as it goes.
This is gonna go overnight.
What temp?
About 225 uncovered.
So, we're gonna make
the baja sauce?
-Yes.
-Okay.
Mayonnaise.
-Mayonnaise.
-A little bit of salt.
-Yep.
Some fresh-squeezed
Key lime juice.
-Key lime juice.
-Yes.
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
You get the acid right there.
Okay.
We're ready to build it?
Yes.
Look at this
bone-in pork butt.
You know it's done
when you can grab that.
I love that you roasted it
without a lid on it.
You really get to build
some of that texture
and some of that bark.
[ Tongs clack ]
Good amount of salt,
right amount of oregano.
The baja sauce.
Where's the bread
coming for the torta?
From a panadería
in Medford.
That's "Mexican bread shop,"
or "bakery."
-Mm-hmm.
-Look at that beautiful pork.
-Queso fresco...
-Okay.
...chilies toreado.
Fried jalapeños.
The frying of it takes down
the heat a little bit.
You're very gracious
with those.
A lot of avocado.
I like the way this is going.
Pico.
It's been weird all these years
having this named after me --
pico de Guy-o [gallo]
but I just deal with it.
There we go.
♪♪
It's delicious,
it's honest,
but something is going off
in that sandwich
that has me
back to Manzanillo.
I'd go into the big,
open-air markets.
Maybe it's the roasted pork
in the air. I don't know.
The torta is so tender
and light.
The baja sauce
with the lime --
you got to have
enough lime in there.
Queso fresco, you get
a little bit of that saltiness,
a lot of avocado,
good, raw crunch
of the veggies
of the pico de me-o.
[ Chuckles ]
A torta done right
is a very special thing.
That's really done right.
I got a carnitas torta
with a cabbage and lime salad.
It's tender, perfect,
spicy, lean.
What I love most about it
is balance.
The bread-to-meat ratio
is perfect on this.
Fresh Salmon Taco --
beans and rice.
WOMAN: It's just a wonderful
experience --
the best restaurant
in Ashland, bar none.
This is a gem.
It's so great to see
how you've kept it real,
you've kept it simple,
you kept it honest.
This has radiated down
from John and all of us.
John, I hope
you're digging this, man.
She's doing great.
Nicely done.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up --
a bomb barbecue truck
in Spangle, Washington...
I like it, buddy.
...turning
the family cookbook...
Granny pretty much
owns this.
[ Chuckling ] Yeah.
Good job, Granny.
...into a bestseller.
She know you're giving away
the recipe?
Uh, no.
We'll keep it between us.
Okay.
♪♪
I'm just like everybody else --
I'm always on the quest
for great barbecue.
I'm 25 minutes south
of Spokane, Washington,
in Spangle.
Yep.
This is the whole town.
Two brothers learned barbecue
from their dad
who's a heavy
equipment operator.
They've got
the Scandinavian background,
and they took off
down to Mississippi
to fetch themselves
an old hickory smoker.
This is Nordic Smoke.
♪♪
Combo plate.
Everything they make
is absolutely amazing.
We got our smoked
mac and cheese coming out.
Can't really get any better
smoked flavor
than from these guys.
FIERI:
That would be Norwegian brothers
Dusty and Kacy Tellessen.
DUSTY: It was our old man
that got us into it.
I mean, he always had
big smokers and all that.
Backyard tinkerer.
FIERI: And they turned
his backyard hobby
into their own barbecue trailer
with a twist.
We smoke it
with maple onion smoke.
"Maple onion smoke"?
Yep -- throw an onion
in there, in the fire.
It's kind of
our own deal, man.
You just walk by, and you can
smell it, and it's just so good.
SERVER: Brisket sandwich.
The brisket is excellent.
It's really juicy,
the meat's just fall-apart.
I'm hungry.
So, what are we making?
Beer-butter injection
for the brisket.
Fire away.
We hit it with the butter,
onions, minced garlic,
beef broth, brown sugar,
chili powder.
Okay.
Dark beer.
I've been thirsty
the whole time.
Oh, it's --
-Oh, yeah, it's for the...
How long is this
gonna cook down?
About 10-15 minutes.
-Puree it?
-Yep.
Sauce is done.
Dry rub?
Yep. Smoked paprika,
brown sugar, celery salt,
sea salt, pepper,
and allspice.
[ Whistles ]
A lot of allspice.
Yeah, man.
That's the Norwegian.
And here's our brisket.
Ready to go.
Inject it with
the SpitJack Injector.
Yeah.
Normally, we try to do
about eight vials.
On one brisket?
On one, big brisket.
Yeah, dude.
Okay,
so dry-rub it.
How long's
this gonna go down?
12-14 hours.
-225?
-Yep.
Next up.
We're gonna make
mustard barbecue.
Good, old Carolina
I'm a big fan.
Prepared mustard.
Salt, pepper, brown sugar,
chili powder...
Tomato paste?
...tomato paste,
apple cider vinegar.
A little shot of water
just to thin her out.
Let this cook down
how long?
About 10 minutes.
You go right from there
to a squirt bottle,
and we're good to go?
Yep.
-I like it, buddy.
-Okay.
-Pull the brisket?
-Yeah.
And we let these briskets rest
for about 2 to 3 hours.
Nice,
little smoke ring there.
We got a pub roll
from a local bakery.
Mmm.
I pick that allspice up
right off the bat.
Yeah.
Pick up a little bit
of that beer.
Not dry by any means.
♪♪
That's pretty dynamite.
No offense to your bun here,
I'm just...
[ Laughs ]
None taken, man.
That is the lingonberry
barbecue sauce.
Lingonberry.
That is definitely Norweigian.
Yep.
Oh, that's lingonberry
and allspice all day long.
That's good sauce.
None on my face, right?
-No, you're good.
-I'm good.
Okay,
we've got a brisket combo.
Just so tender. It just melts
right in your mouth.
MAN:
And when you put a little bit of
the mustard sauce on top of it,
oh, it's to die for.
Can I get an order
of the brisket chili, please?
You got it, man.
I've literally driven
over 50 miles to find them.
FIERI: Which is either
setting up shop all over Spokane
or working right here
in their hometown of Spangle.
Was Spangle
ever a bigger town?
No.
It was smaller, but...
WOMAN: Community pride
for Nordic Smoke is amazing.
We're pretty proud of them.
Kacy's a veteran,
and the community really likes
that it's a veteran-owned
business.
How long
were you in?
Four years
in the Marine Corps.
Thank you
for your service.
-Yeah, appreciate that.
-Really appreciate it.
MAN: Well, the two brothers,
they take
a lot of pride
in what they do.
They go above and beyond
the call of duty
when it comes to their barbecue.
Can I get ribs
and smoked beans, please?
SERVER: All right.
The best ribs
I have ever had.
MAN: The baked beans
are fantastic, too.
It's a homemade family recipe
that they've carried on
for generations.
Okay, my brother,
St. Louis rib --
so a spare rib
cut down.
A little olive oil.
So, the same dry rub
that we did.
Ready for the smoke, man.
About five hours, 225.
And just a little
apple cider spritz.
Yep.
I hit it with that
about every hour,
and then there's
a honey-maple beer glaze.
Yeah.
Did you fall a lot
as a kid?
Oh, yeah.
Time for the beans.
-Yep.
-Now, whose recipe is this?
Grandma's.
So canned
pork and beans.
Yep.
Black beans, red kidneys,
butter beans, onion,
raw jalapeños,
brown sugar...
Okay.
...ketchup,
apple cider vinegar.
-Fried-up ground beef.
-Yep.
And then some
hickory-smoked bacon crumbles.
-With the fat?
-With the fat.
What did she call this,
"Kitchen Sink"?
Yeah.
And just some salt
and pepper, man.
So, you're gonna bring
all that smoke flavor in.
Yep.
225, about 4 hours.
Okay.
Let's make it happen, Captain.
All right, man.
How many ribs you give
in an order?
Three.
I don't need
any more than that.
That's a big rib.
Mmm.
Great smoke.
You get the dry rub
and then the mop
that you're throwing on there,
and that combined with the fat
of the rib -- wow.
That was a good rib.
And where's the beans?
Now, that...
That's it.
♪♪
Oh-ho.
Those are good baked beans.
Different textures
of the beans --
the crunchy ground beef,
the little nuggets of bacon
with that delicious bark.
Granny nailed it.
Granny pretty much
owns this.
[ Chuckling ]Yeah.
Good job, Granny.
Does she know
you're giving away the recipe?
Uh, no.
We'll keep it
between us.
Okay.
You guys,
don't tell anybody, okay?
Ribs and beans.
The ribs are my favorite
that Nordic Smoke does.
There's so much meat on them.
The beans have a nice texture.
They pop in your mouth.
Meat combo and smoked mac,
dude.
-Thanks, man.
-Enjoy it.
-Amazing food.
-Smoked to perfection.
-Lucky to have them here.
-You've done it right.
-Awesome. Thanks, man.
-Well done, my friend.
-Well done.
-Appreciate it.
So, was that another righteous
road trip or what?
But don't you worry --
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
-[ Laughs ]
-That looks like you.
Guy...
Guy out of the shower.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪