You know,
folks ask me all the time,
"Hey, Guy,
that place you went to
in that one town
that served that one dish,
how are they doing after
'Triple D'?"
You know what? I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation."
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cookin'.
Like on this trip --
a dive in Miami
where their take on bar food...
Do you have a license
to do this?
...is setting
a whole new standard.
I'm over it. You can do
your wings your way.
Mmm.
And it's smoking-hot
in Des Moines,
where this eclectic
barbecue joint...
Hillbilly sushi roll.
...has gone Japanese.
Gonna eat those greens
till my head falls off.
Plus, over in Omaha,
a family carrying on
the legacy of their founder.
You don't watch out,
what's gonna happen next
is the Food Network's
gonna be here.
And in Tarpley, Texas...
That's not gonna be bad
at all.
...I'm catching up
with the O.G.,
the premiere, the inaugural...
Can I get some horns
and splashing and...?
Yep, it's literally
"Triple D" 101.
-That's --
-It's been a long time!
Old friends...
Nice to meet you.
...new places, and more
off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, we're here to check out
a joint that we like
to call a "Triple D" O.G.
That means it was
the first location
on the first episode
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Oh, the place is funky,
the food is legit,
and it's still cranking it out.
This is Mac & Ernie's.
Here's the quail
for that FRY-FECTA coming out.
After "Triple D" came,
it's really taken off
with a cult following.
Thank you.
Naylene has a personality
bigger than Texas,
and she has done so much
for the area.
She's put us on the map.
FIERI: "She" would be owner
Naylene Dillingham,
and "us" would be
Tarpley, Texas.
This is the form of
drive-through here in Tarpley?
-Yeah.
-Give me a hug.
Ah, you're awesome.
And Naylene's
one of those people
I just love catching up with.
Let's go back
a long time ago.
I call you
a "Triple D" O.G.
because you were part
of the beginning of me
finding these culinary
kitchen warriors,
and that's what made
"Triple D" pop.
Well, thank you!
Can I get some horns
and splashing and announcements
and a lower-third banner?
[ Laughs ]
When we came to do it,
why did you agree to do it?
'Cause I thought
it would be fun.
I just remember
so many things.
You wouldn't tell me what was
in the Cabrito burger.
I still won't.
I call them
"cabrito burgers" because,
if you say "goat burger,"
it doesn't have the same ring.
-It doesn't...
-Would you like to cook one?
Yeah. I want to
make one, though.
Well, no,
I can't let you do that.
Why?
Because I won't tell you
what's in it.
-Tell me the recipe.
-No.
NAYLENE: I don't share the
recipe for the cabrito burger.
I never will.
Come on!
-No.
-After all these years?
My staff doesn't even know.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Wow. That's not
gonna be bad at all.
It's a little morsel
of delight.
-Wow. That is delicious.
-Thank you.
This is an ancho chili
that's dried.
You did a quail
with an ancho chili.
-Yes.
-We're gonna put some honey.
Clove of garlic.
What happened to the lid
on this bad boy?
It got misplaced.
I swear that I'm losing
my hearing from this thing!
Huh? Oh-ho-ho!
You just try to get
as much glaze on there
that you can with --
That's right.
-Hoo. That is juicy.
-Mm-hmm.
Fresh definitely makes
a difference on this.
I've ripped that recipe
off six ways to Sunday.
Cool!
I have used that recipe
a million times.
It's still one of the most
popular things on the menu.
Without question.
Wow! That is good.
What did you bring?
Oh, the shrimp.
'Cause you didn't have shrimp
when I was there.
-I know. I...
-I love shrimp.
-I'm sorry.
-You have none in there?
-No.
-Damn!
Finally.
It's only been 11 years.
I mean, I've seen an order
late to a table before,
but that's a --
A long time!
It's fresh.
Texas gulf shrimp.
And I'm just gonna dip them
into my egg wash, put them
in my seasoned flour,
toss them around.
I've got my oil at 350 degrees,
and I'm gonna drop it in.
FIERI: And what's fried shrimp
without tartar sauce?
NAYLENE: Mayonnaise,
dried onion, dill relish,
sweet relish,
dried dill, black pepper.
I use a lot of dill in this
because I like the dill
against the shrimp.
We got a shrimp.
♪♪
Fantastic. Mmm.
Little dill in there?
Mm-hmm.
We go to the coast often,
and we have yet to find anyone
who can prepare shrimp
as well as she does.
It never has
a greasy taste at all.
I can feel
the crispy layer of it.
The flavor. You just want
to discover what's in it.
But she won't tell me.
You know what I love? Is
you haven't changed one bit.
I mean, what is your
culinary philosophy?
You should cook
what you like to eat.
You cook what you want
to cook when you cook it,
how you cook it.
Lamb's popular today.
People will come in and ask
for fried lamb chops.
Mmm. That might be the best
lamb chop I've ever had.
I've had...eight so far.
You should see their faces when
I tell them that you had eight.
That's not okay
to lie to the viewers.
I've had...eight so far.
-[ Laughs ]
-What are some other menu items?
The FRY-FECTA.
It's a chicken-fried quail,
a chicken-fried lamb chop,
and a chicken-fried
filet mignon.
I'm gonna bread the quail first
because it takes longer to cook.
I drop it in the seasoned flour,
into the buttermilk,
back into the seasoned flour,
and then into the fryer.
And then, while that's cooking,
I'll bread the lamb chop
and the filet.
And that is the FRY-FECTA.
You deep-fry filet mignon?
Why do you want to chew and chew
when it's like buttah?
Oh.
Is this your mom's gravy?
-Yes, it is.
-Fantastic.
And it's made with
a roux, bacon, serranos,
milk, and stock.
This is delicious.
I love the FRY-FECTA.
I love the name.
One of my favorite meals
is the lamb chop.
The quail was really juicy,
the filet mignon was great,
and the gravy
is really yummy, too.
With her putting all three
of them together,
it really hits everybody's
taste buds just perfect.
Give me the rest
of the story.
What else is going on inside
the world of Mac & Ernie's?
-Now, that's a shelf.
-It is.
Feel like I'm in college.
Do we call it
a building or a shed?
I think it's a shack.
FIERI: So, the million-dollar
question to me is,
is she still cooking out
of that random, little shack?
NAYLENE: I had an opportunity
to buy the restaurant
down the street
and attach the little building.
And the window
that we pass food through,
we still pass food
through that window.
It's just all inside now.
♪♪
It's really amazing
to see how far she's come,
but really keeping
to the traditions
that made her who she is today.
FIERI:
When I give you that title
of being a "Triple D" O.G.,
it's what set the standard.
When we found you,
we're like,
"Man, we're gonna go
to the ends of the Earth
to find these locations
and to find these real people."
And thank goodness
we met you.
I'm sure thankful
you did.
Thanks so much.
You're so welcome.
Maybe you can throw some
Mac and Ernie's swag
our way one day,
you know.
Maybe a burger recipe.
Dream on, little dreamer.
"Dream on,
little dreamer!"
♪♪
I'm still gonna hold out
for the recipe.
I mean, it might take
another 11 years,
but I think I can
eventually convince her.
All right, coming up...
Okay, is this new math?
'Cause you got seven.
...another "Triple D"
from way, way back,
where the bar-food basics...
Probably gonna get kicked out of
the national wing-eating club.
...are a little more refined.
-Was like buttah.
-Right on.
FIERI: One of the most memorable
"Triple D" stories
from back in the day
is in Miami --
actually, in a location
you wouldn't expect.
I'm here in Miami,
where 20 years ago,
a flight attendant
and a carpenter
took a chance
to open a restaurant.
Now, it didn't look like much --
it's here in a strip mall --
but they had a plan.
And that plan definitely worked.
This is Scully's Tavern.
Grilled wings over here!
MAN:
Better than just bar food.
This stuff is just
top-of-the-line.
I think Chris and Cass
were one of the originals,
and they are still abuzz.
Order in the window!
Three tacos!
FIERI: That would be
Chris and Cass Hirsh,
whose place had me
scratching my head.
When I pulled up and I looked
at the exterior of the joint,
I'm like, "All right.
Maybe a fried potato skin,
some bad nachos."
Instead, I get escargot.
CHRIS: Six mushrooms.
Okay, is this new math?
'Cause you got seven.
-There you go.
-Okay.
The Belgian escargot.
Put a little oil in it first
just to get it started.
Our garlic butter.
So, everybody comes
to temperature together.
We're gonna take out
our mushrooms.
Take our escargot.
-Ohh.
-Little provolone cheese.
Throw that up in
the cheese melter.
You got it.
There we go.
Look at that.
Mmm.
That was so delicate.
it was like buttah.
You're having
the escargot?
CHRIS:
It was on the menu before,
and we didn't sell a lot of it,
but we sold a lot of it
after that.
FIERI:
But even their bar-food classics
are done the Scully's way.
Buffalo wings are hot sauce
and butter, and that's it.
Okay?
No, no, no, no.
We don't make it like that.
So, when anybody
starts tweaking it,
I get a little skeptical.
-Hot sauce.
Worcestershire.
Fresh, chopped garlic.
-Whipped butter?
-Butter.
We fry it.
We grill it.
We fry it, we grill it,
we toss it into the sauce,
and then we eat it,
you know?
-You have a license to do this?
-Not yet.
He's never seen it like that.
Very savory.
Probably gonna get kicked out of
the national wing-eating club.
Sacrilege.
Okay. I'm over it.
You can do your wings your way.
This is some
legit food, brother.
You got them oysters
coming, right?
FIERI:
And wait till you see
what he's doing
with Buffalo sauce now.
Buffalo oyster!
Pickup, please!
Nobody expects Scully's Tavern
to have this type of dish.
It's more of a gourmet item.
I just wanted to do something
different and created it.
These oysters
are from Apalachicola.
Then we're gonna put them
into our dry batter.
Our flour consists of paprika,
steak seasoning,
and granulated garlic.
And then we're gonna fry them.
We're gonna take our arugula.
We're gonna bed it.
They are topped
with blue cheese.
And then, on top of that,
is pepperoni chips
and our Buffalo wing sauce.
This is one of our
most popular dishes.
Everybody loves them.
MAN:
That hot sauce on them
definitely takes it
to a different level.
I got one Buffalo oyster up!
This new buffalo style
is definitely closing in
as my favorite oyster.
FIERI: But that's not the only
new trick from this old dog.
Let's get into the hunch.
If somebody says
they want a fish sandwich
and they look in the dictionary
for a definition...
that should be
the sandwich.
They're not just serving
the mahi between bread anymore.
He's smoking it, chopping it,
and making
a South Florida staple.
CHRIS:
Our smoked-fish dip.
Shallots, Dijon mustard,
our horseradish, lemon juice,
and a little bit
of vinegar-based pepper sauce.
We're gonna add mayonnaise
at the end to bind it together.
Great smoky flavor.
Just great texture.
Let me have two
smoked-fish dips.
It's all fish. There's not
a lot of filler in it.
Has really nice,
mild seasonings,
and it has nice,
big chunks of fish in it.
One of my favorites.
Lot of people pass us by,
don't know what
they're gonna miss.
You don't know, do you?
I was here for the original
filming when Guy came.
You're watching
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I was 10 then. So I'm 21 now.
-Right on.
-Dude, you did it.
-Thank you much.
-4 for 4.
-Appreciate it.
-You score.
-I'm out the door.
-I hear you.
See ya.
So, here's the deal.
As long as Chris keeps
that escargot on the menu,
I'll come back
every time I'm in Miami.
And coming up in Omaha,
another menu shocker...
Eat it!
...I had to hear
to believe.
Once you're "ear,"
you love it.
♪♪
So, on a trip to Omaha,
I checked out
an old-school soul-food joint
that was literally
in an old school.
Well, now they're
getting ready to move
into an even bigger location,
but they're still keeping the
legacy of their founder alive.
This is Big Mama's Kitchen.
♪♪
Fried chicken.
WOMAN:
Each meal is made with love
so that when you leave
through that door,
you know you got
some great home cooking.
It is comfort food.
It really is.
FIERI: Patricia Barron,
a.k.a. Big Mama,
opened this place
after a stint in the Navy,
30 years
at a phone company...
Order!
...and this little gem.
Now, did I hear correctly
that you went to clown school?
[ Laughs ]
Yes, I did.
Who told you that?
[ Laughing ]
Sadly, Big Mama
passed away in 2018.
But her daughter Gladys
is keeping things running...
There's a cat sandwich
on here with a fry.
...and making sure
no one forgets
Big Mama or her food.
She loved to cook,
and she wanted to share
her gift with others.
That oven-fried chicken?
unmatched.
We're gonna cook chicken
like my grandma
taught me
how to cook chicken.
We're gonna oven-fry it.
-Oven-fry it. Okay.
-Yeah.
I just pour the buttermilk
on it.
We're gonna hit it
with all the seasonings?
-Yes.
-The lemon pepper.
-No-salt seasoning.
-Okay, so we let those marinate?
Usually we let it
sit overnight.
This is
self-rising flour.
Fry it 15 minutes.
Then I turn it.
And then cook it 15 minutes
on the other side.
It's baked while it fries.
All right.
Let's eat it.
Mmm.
That's pretty tasty.
Good chicken. Mmm.
FIERI: And this
third-generation chicken
didn't just stop with Big Mama.
It's not passed on to her
granddaughter Diondria,
who's mastered the art of
her cold fried-chicken sandwich.
DIONDRIA: Lettuce, tomato,
onions, and now chicken.
FIERI:
And she's spicing it up
with Big Mama's
vinegar-based sweet-onion sauce.
DIONDRIA: Vinegar, mustard,
onions, poppy seed,
little arrowroot,
a little garlic.
Big Mama's secret seasoning.
FIERI: Well, that's a secret
she happened to share with me.
Ah!
Sugar, salt,
cumin, paprika...
So, there's a little
paprika in there.
...chili powder.
Voilà.
Big Mama's cold
fried-chicken sandwich.
The flavors just explode
in your mouth.
♪♪
How much fun are you
having right now?
More fun than what
I thought I would. [ Laughs ]
They also made a pig-ear
sandwich together.
Oh.
He was very nervous
about trying the pig ear.
Right "ear," right now.
This'll be the highlight
of your day.
Eat it!
It is very tasty.
I would call it natural bologna.
I didn't really think I was
gonna be too big of a fan.
Once you're "ear,"
you love it.
Yes.
How many "ear" jokes
have I tried to pull off
that you've not even
smiled at?
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
Fortunately, Big Mama's also got
some more mainstream
Southern soul traditions.
For Big Mama, if something
was to be labeled soul food,
it had to have
collard greens in it.
And she and I had talked
for a long time
about creating a nacho dip
made with collard green.
So, we're gonna start with
margarine and a little flour.
We're gonna make a roux.
Add some milk.
My grandmother called the juice
from cooking your greens
"hot liquor."
A little cayenne,
crushed red pepper,
cheddar cheese, and Monterey.
And we're ready to add
the collard greens.
Put a nice little handful
and stir some more.
Ms. Winky's collard green dip.
The collard green dip
is delicious.
WOMAN:
You get a lot of the cheese,
a little bit
of the collard greens.
You get spicy along
with some refreshing coolness.
I like hot food!
I don't know why
I'm speaking louder.
GLADYS:
One of Big Mama's last dreams
was to see
the restaurant get moved,
so we will be moving very soon
to a brand-new location --
the Seventy Five North project.
MAN: They still carry on
the legacy of Big Mama
and that commitment to family.
FIERI: I mean, it's just crazy.
People are packing in here.
I mean, if you don't watch out,
what's gonna happen next
is the Food Network's
gonna be here.
[ Laughs ]
You know, I bet you Big Mama
is smiling down right now
with all they're doing
to keep her memory
and those delicious
recipes alive.
Now, coming up...
-Whoa!
-Yeah, I like those.
...a barbecue joint
in the Midwest
mixes down-home country
with other countries.
Hillbilly sushi roll.
-Ah, that's tasty. Nice job.
-Thank you.
♪♪
Here's the story.
I go into this joint
in Des Moines, Iowa,
where a chef is
dishing out ridiculous ribs
and killer Southern cooking --
not what I was expecting
in the middle of the Midwest,
and the name doesn't
exactly help explain it.
This is Flying Mango.
Half-rib dinner,
red beans, and rice.
WOMAN: Flying Mango is the place
that we take all of our friends
and family
when they come into town.
WOMAN: Ever since Flying Mango
was on "Triple D,"
we made sure we had
a standing reservation
every Friday night
at 6:00 p.m.
FIERI: When I first met chef
and owner Mike Wedeking,
I knew he looked
really familiar.
Is it the dad
from "Family Ties"?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
That's exactly who it is.
Mr. Keaton.
♪♪
Okay, Mr. Keaton,
let's roll.
What are we gonna make?
We're gonna make some ribs?
We're gonna make
some rib rub first.
Rib rub.
Ba-dum, ba-dum, bum, bum.
Take paprika.
Just a titch of, uh --
-A what?
-Titch.
That's just a little more
than a skosh of onion powder.
Has anybody ever
heard of titch?
Black pepper, salt,
cayenne,
celery salt,
crushed red-pepper flakes.
-Whoa!
-Yeah, I like those.
Garlic powder,
ancho-chili powder.
Would you like
your ribs, sir?
Okay, so out to the smoker.
And what are we smoking with?
Just cherrywood.
The rib is tender.
Great dry rub.
-That is tasty. Nice job.
-Thank you.
FIERI: And the ribs aren't the
only thing smoking these days.
We're gonna smoke
some duck breast
and some blueberries
to top the duck breast.
We don't season them at all
because the smoke
is the seasoning,
as far as I'm concerned.
45 minutes to an hour to rare,
and that's where we want them.
Now we're just gonna put
the blueberries on
for about 15, 20 minutes just to
get a little essence of smoke.
I like to crisp up the skin,
use a little grill on it.
FIERI: And he's serving it up
with a true Southern staple.
WEDEKING:
We're gonna drop a little
goat-cheese grits on here,
make a little cake out of it.
Goat cheese, some butter,
and some heavy cream.
Three minutes,
we're gonna flip it over
and brown the other side.
Fresh blueberry puree there
just to add a little zest.
Smoked blueberries.
Little goat-cheese grit cake.
Little asparagus.
And we're good to go.
Smoked duck breast
with blueberry glaze.
The smoked duck breast
is perfectly cooked.
Not too much smoke.
It tasted amazing.
The blueberry sauce on it
was killer.
Amazingly tender.
Absolutely phenomenal.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
WEDEKING:
We are starting a new menu.
One of the feature items
on the menu
will be called What Guy Had.
And that'll have a smoked
catfish cake, ribs,
red beans, and rice,
and collard greens.
And tell me about the collards.
Walk me through this.
-You're using pig fat in there?
-Yep.
-A little tarragon vinegar.
-Nice.
Some onion.
Dark brown sugar.
Fat cap off a smoked
pork shoulder.
And how long are
those gonna cook?
45 minutes.
Dig it.
Mmm.
Delicious greens.
Tender. They got
a nice bite to them.
Gonna eat those greens
till my head falls off.
FIERI:
And now he's taken those greens
to a whole new level
with this bad boy.
Our soon-to-be-world-famous
Hillbilly sushi roll.
We're gonna take
some chopped brisket.
It's been smoked.
Add some blanched
sweet potatoes.
Bit of rice.
Charred red onions.
Stir it up. Put it in the
skillet for four or five minutes
just to bring it up
to serving temperature.
And then we'll roll it
in some blanched collards.
Smoked tomato puree.
Top it off with a little
horseradish. And that's it.
-Hillbilly sushi roll.
-All right!
Hillbilly sushi roll
is pretty epic.
The brisket and the rice
wrapped up in the collard green
with the sweet potato in it --
oh, yeah, it's very good.
♪♪
I just will never be able
to fully express my gratitude
for this whole experience.
Once the shoot was done,
I went to be with
my terminally ill sister.
My sister watched it
probably 14 times in a row.
It's the last time
I saw her laugh.
And she passed
on New Year's Day.
And it is by far and away
the greatest gift
I've ever received.
You put a lot of yourself
in this. You can tell.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
Well, right now,
it's twice in a lifetime.
Nice job, man.
Really nice.
♪♪
Well, that's what being part
of the Triple D Nation
is all about --
just like the dive in Miami
doing bar food their own way,
Omaha soul food
fulfilling Big Mama's dreams,
the eclectic barbecue spot
in Des Moines
tricking out their menu,
and, in the heart of Texas,
who could forget Naylene
at the capital of Flavortown?
So, folks, we got plenty
more joints to check out.
We'll see you next time
on "Triple D Nation."
All right. Well, go park
your horse and --
Or do we carhop?
[ Laughs ]
You can carhop.
No.
I'm not going out there.
I get out there,
the horse is gonna kick me.
-Horsehop?
-Yeah. Horsehop.