Hey, there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Here we go.
...we're throwing down...
And we're off to the races.
...with a one-two
pork and pasta punch.
That marinara is lookin'
for a full fist fight.
Like in Spokane, Washington...
You are a dangerous,
dangerous man.
...at a hole-in-the-wall
culinary powerhouse.
That is a one-way ticket
to Flavortown, bro.
Plus, things are getting real
in the Windy City...
This is the "Welcome to Chicago,
California Boy."
...with old-school Italian...
Wow.
This guy's a gangster.
...and a barbecue specialty
straight out of Hong Kong.
I have had some steam baths,
but this one's really weird.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in the great city
of Chicago,
one of my favorite food towns,
and I'm in an area
known as River North.
And I'm here to check out --
what would you expect --
all right, Italian joint.
Now, some will come
and some will go,
but I'm looking for ones
that are like the old school,
30-year joints.
Oh I got one you got
to check out.
This is the Bella Luna Café.
♪♪
Comin' around the bend.
There's nothing else like this.
Ravioli up.
It's home-style Italian cooking.
Just like my mom.
I feel like I'm with my family
when I come here.
FIERI: 'Cause it's the food
Danny Alberga grew up with,
which he's been serving here
since 1988.
Same menu, same everything.
What year was this --
I mean, Capone himself
have this?
It's about 25 years old.
These ovens are mostly used
in Chicago.
They're built for bakeries,
mostly.
-When you're doing deep dish...
-Yeah.
...you want an oven that cooks
like a bread oven.
Chicago deep dish, sausage, up.
Deep dish?
You got to come here.
It's just better.
The crust is amazing.
Light, airy, buttery.
Let's talk about
making great pizza.
We're making our famous
pizza dough.
Flour. Semalina flour next.
A little sugar.
To sweeten up the dough
a little.
Little salt. Olive oil.
Here is our mix between
live yeast, hot water...
Warm water and...
...and a little bit of
olive oil.
That definitely needs some oil.
It's 30 years old, you know?
-Do you have anything new?
-Everything works like a top.
You got to keep it
in tip-top shape over here.
We're gonna grease the pan
with bacon fat.
Let it proof.
-What are we gonna put on it?
-Sausage.
All right, let's make
some sausage.
-We ground the pork ourselves.
-Pork butt in-house. Okay.
-We start out with fennel.
-I get mental with the fennel.
Paprika. Salt.
Where did the recipe come from?
My ma had a little something
to do with that.
I think your ma had a lot
to do with it.
Pepper. Red wine.
You'll let this rest.
And we're ready to
rock and roll.
Do you sleep?
I go to the gym at 5:00
in the morning, work all day.
-You're an animal.
-That's it.
Let's make this pizza.
So the dough's proofed.
Start putting a little edge
on there.
That's edgy.
Sausage goes first.
Wow.
You give the sausage up, huh?
Come on. You can't be cheap.
Whole-milk mozzarella.
Got it.
Tomato sauce.
-Just ground tomatoes?
-Right.
Now you're gonna season it up.
Oregano. Parmesan cheese.
Don't be cheap with the cheese.
-Top that pie, Chef.
-You got it.
-25 minutes?
-We're ready.
-Come on, baby.
-There you go.
That's a lot crispier
than I see most Chicago pizzas.
I mean, it's not that big,
spongy deep --
-That's not my style.
-No.
Do you throw people out
if they eat it with a fork?
Deep dish you can use a fork.
Mmm.
The sausage is outstanding.
All that rendered-down fat,
I mean, it just soaks
right into that pie.
All that fennel,
that red wine comin' through,
that right there was
the best combination
between deep dish
and thin crust.
You have enough oil in there
that it's almost frying
the bottom of that.
It's got its own
crispy texture.
The tomatoes are just bright
and fresh and vibrant.
Dynamite.
Here's a Chicago-style
deep-dish pizza.
It is fantastic. Crispy crust.
Just the right amount of cheese
and sausage.
All right, tell me the truth,
buddy of mine,
what do you think?
It tastes fresh,
especially the sausage.
-Do you cook?
-Can't cook worth nothin'.
No.
My name is Truth.
I got to tell you the truth.
-Well, my name's Cook.
-[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: I'm also looking for
an amen on the rest of the menu.
The one and only
Rocco DiSpirito.
What makes great Italian food,
in your opinion?
-Usually a mama.
-Okay.
For someone that learned
from a mama like this guy did,
you can tell,
it's the hallelujah chorus
of Italian homemade food.
Goosebumps. It's magical.
Rápido, rápido.
Everything is fresh.
The pastas are phenomenal.
Got ravioli up in the window.
Homemade. Filled with
the ricotta and meat.
In my opinion, it's one of
the best things on the menu.
All right, Chef.
This is the filling for...
For the raviolis.
You start out
with some olive oil.
Okay.
Ground beef. 80%/20%.
This is the same sausage
we use on the pizza.
Did you always want
to be a chef?
I love to cook.
I always got to eat.
And I didn't have to do
the dishes.
Did he steal my line?
Basil. Plum tomatoes.
-Dude, crush 'em by hand.
-Crush 'em by hand.
Wow.
This guy's a gangster.
Parmesan in there.
A little garlic.
Let it cool down and then we'll
stuff this into the raviolis?
Stuff these into the raviolis.
30-year-old pot here.
You ready?
How about you tell me the things
that aren't 30 years old?
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna make marinara sauce.
Chopped onions.
If your mom was still with us,
I'd call her and say,
"Hey, I found
your colander, ma'am."
'Cause that's full out
of somebody's house.
That's the only thing
I got out of the will.
Are you kidding me?
That's the only thing
they left me.
Chopped garlic.
Isabella tomatoes.
Okay.
-Salt.
-Hit it.
Black pepper. And basil.
So these you're just gonna
cook down till they break down?
I'm gonna smash them down.
See?
I like the old-fashioned way.
Okay.
Let's build these ravis.
First we're gonna start
with the dough.
Flour. Semalina flour.
Eggs. Olive oil.
Salt. A little bit of water.
We let it rest, we run it
through the sheeter,
and we're ready
for our raviolis.
All right, let's see it.
Oh, you're serious?
Every one of these
is made by hand?
Yeah.
-Little bit of ricotta.
-And a little fresh mozz.
Another sheet of dough
right on top.
Trim the edges.
We crimp them with a fork.
You're cooking each ravioli
in its own little basket?
Yeah.
Because they stick together.
Don't you know nothin'
over here?
We got to teach you everything?
-Pull it out al dente.
-Cheese on there.
And we're good to go.
And if you can finish four
of these, you're my hero.
Parsley.
Fresh Pecorino Romano.
Oh, by the way, this was once
a nice part of a coffee/tea set,
and now he's just hammerin' it
with some Pecorino.
Those were left to me
in the will.
Yeah. "It was left to me
in the will."
-Dig in.
-All right.
Look at the size of this thing!
That's how you're supposed
to eat them.
If you really love the big,
thick pastas,
you're gonna love this ravioli.
This is pasta city.
And great...
stuffing inside.
That marinara is lookin'
for a full fist fight.
[ Laughs ]
The garlic and the onion ratio
is over-the-top.
Not the light, delicate,
easygoing, gentle ravioli.
No, this is the "Welcome to
Chicago, California Boy."
It's four raviolis,
but it's a full experience.
-Your ravioli for you, ma'am.
-It's beautiful.
One of the best raviolis
I've seen in this city.
The sauce that comes out of
the top is absolutely fantastic.
You can tell how fresh it is.
ALBERGA:
Meatball mozzarella up!
If you're gonna come to Chicago,
you want to come here.
I think that the reason
you've done so well
and outlasted the comings
and the goings of all
the restaurant joints
is because you're the real deal.
-Thank you.
-Good job, brother.
FIERI: Up next...
a tucked-away treasure
in Spokane, Washington...
This is one of the most exciting
Triple D's
I've seen in quite a while.
...going off-script
with the gnocchi...
You're crushing it.
I mean, bro, crushing it.
...and dishing out
a dirty carnitas combo.
This is like something you have
for your last meal.
♪♪
Yeah, hello. Harmon?
Yeah. It's Guy.
Yeah, no, I'm in Spokane.
Yeah, I'm looking for the place.
I can't find it.
I'm at the corner
of Monroe and Mallon.
Yeah, I know.
You told me the food's amazing.
What kind of food is it?
You don't know?
It changes --
It changes the menu every week?
Anyhow. Listen.
I'm just standing next to some
rundown place.
The place looks like ruins.
Oh!
This is it!
♪♪
All right, guys.
We have a roasted chicken.
It's the best food in town.
We got a minute on the pork.
It's always different,
it's always delicious.
SERVER: Lebanese meatballs.
It's kinda tough to find
something different in Spokane.
We're kind of
a meat-and-potatoes town.
This is big-city food.
FIERI: 'Cause while owner
Tony Brown grew up here,
he cut his teeth in one of
my favorite food towns, Chicago,
and he made sure
to bring all those flavors
back home with him.
We change our menu
all the time.
The first year that we opened,
we did 52 menus in 52 weeks.
-It's pretty stupid.
-Are you still...
-[ Laughs ]
-I didn't want to say it.
One week we would do Thai food,
next week
we would do Mexican food.
So how much of this is
a business and how much of this
is just your personal culinary
Disneyland?
A lot of it's my culinary
Disneyland.
Dirty fries ready for pickup.
FIERI: And this mash-up of
carnitas and fries
is a ride worth jumping on.
They're to die for.
-We're gonna do dirty fries.
-Boneless pork shoulder.
You slice it an inch
and a half thick.
We just do a little bit
of Mexican oregano, dried.
A good healthy bit of salt.
You can't have enough,
especially with all that fat.
Bay leaves.
And then chicken stock.
See what he's doing right there?
He's pouring it in the corners
so he doesn't wash off
the seasoning off the top.
Little bit of OJ.
A little bit of moisture
to work in the steaming process.
Exactly.
Which is gonna really help
break it down.
How long?
325 for probably about
2 1/2, 3 hours.
Okay.
Then when it's ready
for service...
Put it on the flat-top
and then just kinda chop it up.
Right.
Okay, pork's goin',
fries are goin'.
-Aioli.
-We make ours with eggs yolks.
A little bit of garlic.
White wine vinegar.
We're just gonna kinda buzz
that around, get it frothy.
Dijon mustard.
This is my kind of aioli.
Now we're just gonna
emulsify this guy
really slow with the oil.
We're gonna coat the fries
with this?
We're gonna coat
the fries with it.
That's nice.
No diet season up here
in Spokane, huh?
Yeah.
A little bit of lemon juice.
Pinch of salt.
And you can make that at home.
What, did this turn
into a cooking?
What, are you
on Food Network now?
[ Laughs ]
Salsa verde
and then we're done.
Parsley. Green onion.
-Mint.
-The mint is the kicker here.
It brings out
I think a great flavor.
-I love mint.
-Yeah, me too.
Shallots. Lemon zest.
Chili flake. Little salt.
-Black pepper.
-Lemon juice.
And oil will help marry
the flavors.
Yeah, it'll marry it together.
I think if you're gonna eat
a fry, it should be
a damn good fry.
-Mm-hmm.
That's better
than a damn good fry.
Great crunch.
You never see shoestring
that small.
Pork. Aioli.
Salsa verde on there.
Garnish with a little bit
of extra green onion.
The dirty fries.
Don't say we look like twins.
[ Laughs ]
You are a dangerous,
dangerous man.
This just makes all other fries
seem boring.
This is like something you have
for your last meal.
The kicker is the aioli.
No, it's good.
It adds that acid to it.
That is a one-way ticket
to Flavortown, bro.
SERVER: Dirty fries for you.
The meat is super tender.
You get a little bit of salt
and fat to go with fries.
It's the perfect thing
to throw on top.
Lamb kofta.
Ready for pickup.
This food is fantastic here.
Tony's menu kinda hooked me.
Here's a white fish,
in the window.
FIERI:
And that high-end culinary?
Well, it's coming out of a joint
as low-rent as they come.
It's called Ruins because
of the condition
that they first found it in.
Externally you don't really
notice it too much
when you're driving by,
which is part of its charm,
and then when you come in
it's really inviting.
The vibe is really good in here
and it coincides
with the food well.
So, here's the deal.
I'm hanging out in Spokane,
Washington at Ruins.
When we come back,
I think I'm gonna get ruined.
-Gnocchi?
-Gnocchi next.
Oh, gosh.
The gnocchi? Oh, my goodness.
I can't even begin.
It's the best gnocchi
that I've had.
I'll be asleep in booth two.
One, two...
Okay, I got the clapper.
-[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back. In Spokane,
Washington at Ruins.
Oh, yeah.
And the name fits completely.
I was just ruined
by the dirty fries.
It was salty, it was tangy,
it was crunchy, it was creamy,
it was everything.
It was three more hours
on the treadmill.
[ Laughs ]
We got a seafood stew
ready for pickup.
Tony rotates the menu and keeps
it fresh and interesting.
All right, guys.
We have the gnocchi
with bacon and tarragon.
The gnocchi here
is really fabulous
because it's not traditional.
It melts in your mouth.
The bacon just sets it off
as well.
FIERI:
All right, Chef, next up?
Gnocchi.
This is Parisian gnocchi.
It's not made with potatoes.
It's made with
flour and butter.
It's a called a pâte à choux.
Same thing you make, like,
cream puffs.
-Okay.
-Butter into the water.
I'm gonna wait for this guy
to come to a boil.
I know we're gonna add
all of our flour at once.
Here we go!
And we're off to the races.
It's gonna turn into,
like, Play-Doh.
Now we're just gonna work
some ingredients into it.
Gruyère cheese. Dijon mustard.
Tarragon.
Oh, this is a party.
And to really round out
this pâte à choux,
now we start dropping
the eggs in one by one.
Yes, one by one.
And then you want to wait
until it's incorporated.
It starts to almost look like
a plastic-y
kinda really shiny dough.
-Sheen-y, yeah.
-Yeah.
-In this little funky kitchen --
-Uh-huh.
...you are putting this level
of time and attention
together in recipes.
-Yeah.
I love this one because
it's like fine dining.
No, it's not "it's like a,"
it is "a."
This guy's not for real.
So we take this
into a piping bag
and then we're just gonna
pipe it right into
the salted boiling water?
-Yep.
We're gonna parboil them,
yeah, for...
-So they'll set up nice?
-Yep.
Now we're gonna sautée them in
a little bit of butter and oil.
They start to puff up
a little bit.
Put a little crisp to 'em?
Add our bacon in there.
That's my jam.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
Here's the thing,
there's barely enough gluten
to hold this together.
It defies gravity.
If you've misplaced
your dentures,
come on down to Ruins,
'cause you can eat this.
[ Laughs ]
I can't taste anything
out of balance.
Everything is in proportion.
I love this little crunch.
I love where you sautéed it
just to the piece
where a couple of them
aren't surviving
and they just turned into...
-Crisp.
A little cheese fodder
on the bottom.
[ Laughs ]
You know what I don't
understand?
Is why they don't serve that
at the movie theater.
I know. Exactly.
Just put it like
in your fanny pack
and just walk around all day.
[ Laughs ]
Fanny pack.
Hi, guys.
We have a gnocchi with bacon.
The tarragon and the bacon to go
with the gnocchi is excellent.
That's as good as you can get.
This is Harmon, who I was
talking to on the phone,
and my brother Scott.
What do you think?
How's the gnocchi, Harm?
Tender. Tasty.
-Good flavor?
-It's got everything you need.
Roasted chicken in the window.
I wasn't used to Spokane
having food of this caliber.
Everything is just top notch.
This is one of the most exciting
Triple D's
I've seen in quite a while.
-Awesome.
'Cause you're doing what
everybody wants to do.
You find an abandoned location,
you make what you want,
when you want, how you want it,
and you're crushing it.
I mean, bro, crushing it.
Awesome.
Coming up...
an authentic experience
in Chicago...
Hot and fast, baby!
...at a joint goin' whole hog
with their Hong Kong barbecue...
This is like a lost art.
...and legit Chinese classics.
This is gonna turn into
a one-hour show,
me eating all of the chow fun.
♪♪
I'm here in Uptown Chicago
to check out a type
of food you know I love.
It's Chinese but it's
a little bit different.
It's a specialty, and you're
lucky to find it when you can.
We're talking about real-deal
Hong Kong barbecue.
This is Sun Wah Barbecue.
♪♪
This is our barbecue spare ribs.
The food is always fresh,
it's cooked just right.
Chock full of flavor.
Authentic Chinese food
that you can't find
anywhere else, besides home.
FIERI: Which for Eric Cheng,
is Hong Kong --
the place where he ended up
after escaping
Communist China in his 20's.
Give me just
a brief understanding
of how you got
to the United States.
So you came to the United States
through an immigration program?
Yes.
FIERI: But before he got here,
he mastered the art
of Hong Kong barbecue,
which turned
into the centerpiece
of his stateside restaurant.
Hi, guys. Your roast pork.
The roast pork is so unique.
It starts out with crispy,
crispy skin.
Then there's a layer of fat.
And then the meat itself.
It's a great dish.
What are we making?
-The whole pork.
-The whole pig?
-Yes.
-So how do we start?
-So pure cane sugar.
-Yeah.
Okay.
Rice wine. Red vinegar.
This is part of the glaze
that's gonna go
on the outside of the pig?
-Yes.
We're gonna take this
and put it inside the vinegar?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
So this pig, it's been cut.
I see that you put all these
slices into it
so we can make sure we get this
marinade all the way through.
First we go salt, sugar,
and bean sauce.
The bean sauce?
So now we're gonna hang it.
Now put the hot water.
I have had some steam baths,
but this one's really weird.
Now the vinegar that we made
with the maltose.
This is what's gonna make
that skin nice and crackly.
Yes.
We're gonna cook the pig
20 minutes.
Wow.
Take it out,
let it dry for an hour,
and then back in the roaster?
-Yes.
-For how long?
For one hour.
Let's get it!
-Beautiful.
-Now we can cut it.
-Now we eat it?
-Yep.
This is what everybody loves
the crispy skin,
the tender pork.
That's Hong Kong happiness.
-Huh?
-Yep.
This is like a lost art.
-The sound alone...
[ Crunches ]
That's Chinese chicharrón
right there, baby.
Talk about goin'
whole hog.
-Mmm. Dynamite.
-Thank you.
Here we are.
We have a roast pork.
The roast pork is crispy,
and then you've got
that layer of fat
which exudes
the flavor of the pork.
MAN: I've never had it
like that before.
It is really delicious.
So, now, the restaurant is run
by you, your daughters...
Yes.
-...and your son?
-My family.
How long has the restaurant
been here?
Almost 30 years.
-30 years?
-Yes.
Man dad was a Chinese chef.
This was always his go-to place.
He always appreciated the fact
that they did it authentically.
Beef chow fun.
Beef chow fun is white rice
noodles.
The beef flavor is just infused
into the noodles.
It's really, really good.
I know chow fun,
I know rice noodles,
but I've never been
in this process
of making the nice noodles.
We're gonna grind the rice?
-Yes.
-Right in there.
I got to get one
of these machines.
It's like we're making
rice milk or something.
Okay.
So a little oil?
And the cement mixer.
This is how you get it done.
[ Loudly ] It's so quiet!
Now we go to the steamer.
-We're gonna steam that?
-Yeah.
Right.
Okay, I trust you.
-Okay.
-I put a little water in.
All right.
A little beef tenderizer.
-Baking soda.
Sugar.
-Little bit of salt?
-Yep.
In Hong Kong,
they always do it like this.
Hong Kong and Chicago,
close.
A little salad oil?
We're gonna let this marinate
for how long?
Okay.
-So this is the noodle?
-Mm-hmm.
I've been cooking all my life.
I thought I had a good idea
where the rice noodle came from.
Huh.
-And then eating?
-Yeah.
We get to do the eating part,
right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna be great
at that part.
First we need to pan-fry
the noodles.
You're just gonna put
a little char on them.
Onions, the been sprouts.
Hot and fast, baby!
Drop in the noodles.
-Sugar.
-A little salt.
Soy sauce. Sesame oil.
-Now we drop that in?
-Yeah.
Made the sauce right there
in the ladle.
Look at that.
♪♪
Hot! Hot!
-Hot?
-Uh-huh.
It's very delicious.
Not just because you make
the dish fresh,
but because you make
everything in the dish.
Starting with this grinding
the rice,
and putting all that together.
He's very mindful about the way
he worked the wok.
This is gonna turn
into a one-hour show,
me eating
all of the chow fun.
[ Laughs ]
-Delicious.
-Thank you.
Hello. Large beef chow fun.
The noodles are terrific,
the sauce is terrific.
This is my buddy Dane.
You do a fantastic radio show.
I've called in quite
a few times.
Now I finally get to ask you
the hard-hitting questions.
It's like the big switcheroo.
Give me a little breakdown here
on the chow fun.
The beef is exceptionally
tender,
and this is pretty much
as good as it gets.
This is our fish filet
with ginger and green onions.
I met this guy, David,
when I was 16 years old
living in Paris.
The way we discovered
this place is,
I have clients who are Asian
who turned me on to it.
And I came here
and we got carry-out,
but we've been coming back.
This is the best
Chinese restaurant in Chicago.
-Fantastic, my friend.
-Thank you.
Very nice to meet you.
So, that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be lookin' for you
next week on
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
It's like, the biggest thing
was getting the computer here.
That was aggravating.
Let's not have anything
we can track.
[ Laughs ] That's right.
Cash only.
Two-party out-of-state check.
Post date.
[ Laughs ]