You know, people are asking me
all the time, "Hey, Guy.
That one joint you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing
"Triple D," how they doing?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
It's meat mayhem...
[ Vocalizes ]
like in Salt Lake City...
Mmm!
where it's all about meatballs
and Philly cheese steaks.
This is delicious.
And an Italian joint in Arizona
that quickly goes
from off-the-hook...
-Boom.
-Done.
-Ba-da-bing, ba-da-boom.
FIERI:
...to off-the-rails.
This guy is out of bounds.
Plus...
That's Sammy, I'm Guy,
and that's rich.
...we're paying tribute
to the sausage slayer
of Omaha, Nebraska.
That is some
Italian sausage. Mmm!
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors --
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So, we're back here
at Salt Lake City
shooting a little "Triple D."
And we wrapped things up
and I said, "You know what?
It's been since 2008 that I came
and checked out a joint
that's all about Philly.
You know, Philly cheesesteaks,
meatball subs.
The only problem I got
is I'm 2,100 miles away
from Philly.
Well, people around here say,
don't worry about that.
There's only one.
This is Moochie's.
Teriyaki pork steak!
I'm from outside Philadelphia.
Cheesesteaks
here are tremendous,
easily best west
of the Mississippi --
maybe the best I've ever had.
I'm from Philly.
I know what a cheesesteak is.
I know
what the deal is.
Moochie is Joanna,
and along with Don.
Everyone comes here,
gets to know them.
I am Moochie.
Here me roar.
Your name is Moochie?
Well, it's a nickname.
It's an old family nickname.
It's an old
family nickname.
I spent years getting people
to stop calling me that,
'cause I hated it.
-Oh.
Rest of the nation,
when y'all come in
and see Moochie here,
don't call her Moochie.
Shh.
Everybody in town
knows you now, right?
Yes, of course.
Of course.
Everybody in the country
knows you.
-Thank you, Moochie.
-It's been ten years, right?
-Ten years.
-You still look great.
-I know, right?
-She does, huh?
Yeah.
I told you I'm getting younger
and skinnier.
-You and I --
-I know. What can we do?
I remember when we came here.
The Philly cheesesteak
and meatball scene
hadn't really happened
in Salt Lake.
Right.
And now you are the mayors
of Meatball Town.
That's right.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: And Joanna's first
order of business --
making plenty of those famous
Moochie meatballs.
I use a mixture of hot
and mild sausage.
-Italian sausage.
-Yes.
So it's not too spicy,
but it's got enough kick.
-That's right.
-Got it.
And add some eggs
and some garlic.
I'm gonna add salt and pepper,
parsley, bread crumbs,
and then --
uh, one of my little secrets.
I use oatmeal.
We're gonna add
extra-lean ground beef.
Now we mix.
I'm in Camp Moochie,
making meatballs.
You're doing okay.
Now, how many will that make?
-This will be 28.
-Are they ready?
They're ready.
He stuck a fork in and ate it,
and ate the whole thing.
It's like a little kid
with a big lollipop at the fair.
I mean --
Mmm!
FIERI: And those meatballs
actually share
the limelight at this joint.
The Matriarch
of Meatball
and the Chancellor
of Cheesesteak, huh?
You got some very
thin-sliced rib eye steak.
Okay, these are red
and green bell peppers.
And then some
'shrooms here.
Okay.
So, processed American.
One of my crispy rolls.
Now, this right here, folks --
this is how you see it done.
You warm that bread up
by steaming it on top of there.
This guy's legit.
You just want to get
that cheese melting in there.
Oh, yeah!
Yeah.
Mmm! Wow!
And that right there --
that's the goodness.
When we came here,
it was just the one location.
How many sandwiches were you
doing on a given day?
I would say,
a couple hundred.
Now how many you doing?
1,000 sandwiches.
-If these --
-Guy.
You feast is ready.
After "Triple D,"
we started getting so busy
that we would call
people's names out...
Order up, Mike!
RENDI:
...and they couldn't hear us
'cause it would be so crowded.
So we got a microphone.
Andrew.
I just wanna come here
and listen
to all the names get called.
Brad.
Anthony.
Guy.
-What are we packing?
-Teriyaki pork with --
-Whoa!
We went teriyaki on it?
RENDI:
Teriyaki pork with wasabi slaw.
We make our own teriyaki sauce.
It's brown sugar, soy sauce,
lemongrass, ginger root,
and a little bit of cornstarch
to make it thick.
Slice a pork tenderloin.
Then we marinate it
in our teriyaki sauce.
Starting with marinated
pork tenderloin, provolone,
there we go.
Get it off the grill.
Dress it up with wasabi
mayonnaise and slaw.
Our teriyaki pork steak
with wasabi slaw topping.
♪♪
You get that sweet
teriyaki sauce on the pork,
and all of sudden, that wasabi
horseradish on the slaw.
This is delicious.
Teriyaki pork steak!
Got the slaw in it, the cheese,
and the teriyaki gives the pork
kind of a tangy taste to it --
complements it very well.
Very cheesy and messy.
It's got a lot of flavor to it,
just a classic
Moochie's taste.
-What is this?
So, this is another version
of the cheesesteak.
We are just messing around
with this now.
This is a --
-Oh, I'm on the tasting panel?
Yes, you are.
Cheesesteak egg rolls.
I'm using the same meat that
we use in our cheesesteaks,
some chopped onion.
I was originally trying
to come up
with something different
for the State Fair.
You know, it's really nice
having just hand-held food.
And then I'll add the
mushrooms, fresh bell peppers.
Add American
and Monterey Jack cheese.
I'm just gonna take our
egg roll wrapper,
take a nice scoop of cheese
and meat, seal the edges,
and I'm gonna drop them
right in the fryer.
Moochie's cheesesteak egg rolls.
There's one that we do
that's kind of mild,
and one that we do
with a nacho cheese.
The cheesesteaks
always reign supreme.
This is delicious.
Cheesesteak egg rolls!
The crunchy shell
on the outside,
soft in the center
with the meat and cheese --
After one bite, I was sold.
The egg roll is crunchy,
but you recognize it
immediately as the cheesesteak.
It was delicious.
♪♪
So now, we've opened
two more stores.
Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
-Yeah?
-Where's the residual check?
It's in the mail.
RENDI: We got another one
opening in about a month.
So that's gonna be
four total.
Four.
I'm happy for you guys.
You deserve this.
Just so you know, Moochie's sits
inside of the city limits
of Flavortown, folks.
[ Laughter ]
I mean, really --
What would Flavortown be
without a little
Philly influence?
And coming up...
See how this already working?
I'm already working.
FIERI:
...we're off to Arizona...
-Hey.
FIERI: ...where these
Italian stallions...
Oh!
...haven't skipped a beat.
I'm here in Glendale, Arizona
right outside of Phoenix
to visit a joint that's got
a great "Triple D" history.
I remembered the thin crust,
the fresh mozzarella,
and those crazy owners...
-Hit it, boys.
-Oh!
FIERI:
...like 2009 was just yesterday.
We came in for pizza,
threw them a curve ball,
and boy, did it pay off.
Mmm, delicious.
Nice job, man.
This is La Piazza.
We've been to 280 "Triple Ds"
over the years.
La Piazza's
one of our favorites.
They treat us well,
the food is fabulous.
It's a go-to place for us.
What made me come here
was the family element of it.
It seemed real inviting.
-Two pestos to go.
-What do I look like, a caterer?
FIERI:
That's because it's a well-oiled
father-son machine...
Baking a cake
over here or what?
...made up of Dennis Piazza...
No problem.
...and his son, Justin.
Forget about it.
We were supposed to do
a couple of pizzas.
When Guy walked in,
first thing he saw
was my dad's
little special board.
It had spaghetti pie on it,
which is not on the menu
and it's still not.
But Guys said -- "Stop.
We got to do the spaghetti pie.
What is this?"
-Baked spaghetti pie.
Similar to lasagna,
but made with spaghetti.
Dump those in for me,
and I'll get that going --
a little spaghetti there.
See how this is already working?
I'm already working.
So, what are we on now?
Homemade marinara sauce.
Fresh parsley and some
fresh basil, fresh garlic.
Gonna take celery, carrot,
onion -- just a quick chop.
Now I take extra virgin.
Good red wine.
I let this sweat for about four
or five minutes
and add my tomatoes.
Three scoops of this in here,
right in with the ricotta.
Right in with the ricotta.
-Cream?
-Two cups.
Reggiano, Asiago.
Pecorino Romano,
Parmigiano Reggiano.
Just give it
a nice little stir.
So, it's got kind of
a rosy color to it.
-A little rosa.
-You got a word for it all.
Hey!
Okay, mixture goes down?
Couple of ladles of marinara.
Fresh mozzarella.
I cook the pasta al dente
'cause when I go
in the oven with it,
I don't want it
to become mush.
Ooh, look at that!
This show's called
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I travel around the country,
and I watch other people
cook in their restaurants.
Right.
He was great.
I'd hire him in a minute.
Add some marinara.
A little bit of Reggiano.
Right into the oven --
350 for about 30 minutes.
It'll set right up
for the takeout.
There you go.
That's the finished product.
Look at that bad boy.
Take this nice piece like that,
put it in a frying pan,
and put a nice ladle of sauce
here, some fresh mozzarella.
And I'm gonna go right in the
wood-fired oven with this.
-Boom.
-Done.
-Ba-da-bing, ba-da-boom.
After about two minutes
in there, I'll take it.
Stays nice and high
on the plate like that.
There's your baked
spaghetti pie lunch.
[ Whistles ]
You just served me enough
for my whole family to enjoy.
Mmm.
Great texture.
The fresh mozzarella on top,
the handmade sauce -- delicious.
Nice job, man.
FIERI:
And this place is still
putting out real-deal Italian
right in the middle of Arizona.
But these days,
Dennis is more likely to be
on the couch
than in the kitchen.
You know, he's retired now,
and it's my turn
to take care of him.
Thank you.
FIERI: But when he does come in,
he's showcasing the classics
like his polpettes
or fried meatballs.
DENNIS: 80/20 on the ground beef
is always good,
because you don't want
a lot of gristle.
Parsley, salt -- about an ounce.
Regular pepper, garlic --
four ounces.
Then I'm gonna add
a little bread crumbs
here, a little milk,
and a little cheese to start --
Parmigiano Ramono.
I'm gonna add three eggs.
Yeah, if Guy was here,
he'd be right over my shoulder.
"Can I taste that?
Can I touch this?"
Mm.
Look at this guy.
Huh.
You're missing the cheese-eating
and him yelling at me.
He knows what good food is,
and that's the key.
We're gonna put these
in the oven at 350
for about half an hour.
10, 20 seconds in the fryer
each, and they'll be perfect.
FIERI: And they're topped
with marinara,
which has gotten
a lot less complicated.
House marinara is extra virgin
olive oil,
chopped garlic,
chopped onion,
house-peeled
San Marzano tomatoes,
chopped basil, salt,
and pepper.
Done.
Super moist on the inside
and crunchy on the outside,
so it's really tasty.
They are perfectly textured.
I absolutely love
the house-made marinara sauce.
That's my favorite thing
on the menu.
I could drink it.
This guy is out of bounds.
Hysterical.
I was so serious, trying to make
the food come off right,
trying to make sure
everything was technical.
And my dad just came in
and threw a whole
monkey wrench
in that whole thing.
I don't know where Justin is,
but he has got
a hard act to follow.
JUSTIN:
You know what I feel like?
I feel like the opening act
for Metallica now.
That's great.
-Yeah, exactly.
FIERI: Oh, remember those pizzas
we came here for
in the first place?
Well, Justin's about to take
center stage
with a killer pie he's rocking
in the wood-fired oven.
Plus, wait till you see his
encore with that homemade dough.
It's out of control here.
FIERI: We're checking in on
a family-run brick-oven
Italian joint
in Glendale, Arizona.
The grandfather used
to own the Bendix Diner,
a real legend in New Jersey.
The dad's a graduate
of culinary school.
Life's too short
to eat bad food.
And the son's been making pizza
since he was 13 years old,
so he's had plenty of practice
slinging real-deal pie,
like this house-specialty,
the Mediterranean.
Flour it up, stretch it out,
and we're just going to
give it a little twirl.
There you go, nice and soft,
nice and thin.
Fresh mozzarella
goes on first.
It's got homemade pesto.
Alfredo sauce.
Put the pesto in there.
We're gonna whip that up.
Whip it good.
That's the sauce
that goes on the pizza.
I will add a little bit
of shredded mozzarella.
A little olive oil on this one.
Oregano.
In the oven.
We'll watch it and make sure
this cooks real good here.
And look at that.
So we'll take it out here.
Sun-dried tomatoes go on to just
give it a little bit more.
Cheese boiling
on top of a pizza skin.
We'll add fresh feta,
and we're ready to go.
[ Whistles ]
Mmm!
That's great.
That's some really
flavorful pesto, too.
It's so simple, but when you use
great ingredients, so good.
It's like I'm doing
itsy-bitsy spider
with the mozzarella cheese.
Which they're now making
from scratch.
The smaller you can break it up,
the better.
It's curd.
Everything comes from curd,
in the beginning.
Doused with boiling-hot water.
See how it's already
starting to melt together.
We want it to look
almost like dough --
the way dough looks when it's
smooth and it's ready to go.
FIERI: But churning out cheese
isn't the only new chapter
in this family's playbook.
We open the second location
in Downtown Phoenix.
We'll also getting ready
to open a third.
I learned how to make
real Neapolitan pizza.
I threw the oven
that we had away.
I had one shipped
in from Naples.
Best oven in the world.
Justin's constantly working
on upgrading
and trying to improve it,
and it's just gotten better.
FIERI:
And that includes some new hits
on his playlist.
We're making pizza frita,
which is a fried calzone,
which is very popular in Naples.
Dough's ready, stretched out.
Rigotta cheese right
in the center.
Salami, olives,
then we add the tomatoes
that I crushed up by hand.
And fresh mozzarella
on top of that,
and make, like, a turnover.
Like a pocket.
Fold it over.
Now we're ready to go
into the fryer.
And there it is.
Marinara, fresh basil,
and some parmesan.
Pizza frita. Pick up.
[ Rings bell ]
It's crunchy on the outside,
but super-moist in the inside.
The flavors are phenomenal.
FIERI: What do you think
of your son as a chef?
He's the best pizza guy
that I know,
but I've been
in the business 40 years.
Can I save that, 'cause I don't
think I'll hear that ever again.
Without question,
this is in the top
five characters I've ever met.
Hey!
They can serve frozen pizza
and flat soda,
and it'd be worth it
to come watch this guy.
♪♪
Even after all these years,
I can honestly say
Dennis still reigns as one
of the primo personalities.
Now, up next in Omaha...
[ Vocalizes ]
...another unforgettable face...
-Sammy Tomatohead?
-'Cause I got a tomato-head.
FIERI:
...whose legacy is living on.
I think that you're
the real deal, man.
FIERI: I was in Omaha, Nebraska,
back in 2008,
when I met a local legend.
A guy named Sam Amato started
serving sausage
and pepper sandwiches
at a booth at county fairs
and ended up here, serving
his family's Italian favorites.
And these days, his family's
making sure no one forgets old
Sammy Tomatohead.
This is Amato's Cafe.
♪♪
WOMAN:
We've been coming to Amato's
for a long time.
Great family, great friends,
good food.
MAN: Good Italian sandwiches,
good breakfast.
This is "Cheers"
without the beer.
Sam was so excited
to be on "Triple D."
[ Speaking with mouthful ]
He was always so very,
very proud
of his restaurant
and his family.
Sausage and pepper sandwich.
Thank you, sir.
FIERI:
That would be owner Sam Amato,
who brought his old-school
Italian roots
to the people of Omaha.
In my neighborhood,
everyone got a nickname.
-Hey, Sammy.
-Sammy Tomatohead.
Sammy Tomatohead?
'Cause I got
a tomato-head.
Everybody knows Sammy.
Does he just work the room
the whole time?
MAN:
Actually, he does.
FIERI:
Sadly, Sam passed away in 2017,
but his memory lives on through
his friends and loyal customers.
MAN:
Sam was an outgoing person.
He loved people, he loved Guy,
he loved showing
his sausage making.
He really loved it.
Sicilian sausage --
we call it zazitsa.
How do you spell that?
Wrong every time.
Boston pork butt --
we cut it into flanks like that.
A little bit of fennel,
that's what I'm talking about.
Crushed reds.
We're having, like,
food opera at Flavor Town.
Some people get to go
to Disney Land
and ride their favorite ride.
Me, I get to get make sausage
in Omaha.
This is my Disney Land.
[ Vocalizes ]
-The bread...
-Whoa-oh.
-...sausage...
-Whoa-ha.
-...the sweet pepper sauce.
-[ Fieri whistles ]
That's it.
Now that is what
I'm talking about.
This is how the tune goes.
Mmm!
I've had sausage, man...
That is some Italian sausage.
Look at that.
You got that
over there, okay.
That's the
"Get away from me," okay?
♪♪
FIERI:
Homemade sausage is one thing,
but scratch-made ricotta,
now that had my attention.
You know that is just,
like, it, right?
A gallon of milk.
Your precise measuring skills...
Yes, amaze you, doesn't it?
-Yes.
-Half and half.
Quart of water.
3 tablespoons of sugar.
We got a little froth
on the outside,
now we're gonna add
the sea salt.
Whoa, whoa!
Ah!
-Ah!
3 tablespoons of lemon juice
into the buttermilk.
[ Whistles ]
-Instant ricotta.
-Look at it.
See how it
shocked it already?
[ Electricity buzzes ]
You didn't want to cook
with all this, did you?
No.
Nice, warm, and gentle.
It's the best
right out of the pan, Guy.
Nothing like it.
SAMMY:
We're gonna make pancakes.
Not normally the way the show
goes that we make ricotta cheese
and then pancakes,
but I'll follow your lead.
Going right to
the heart of it.
Wow. Mmm!
Good stuff.
That's rich, man.
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
That's Sammy, I'm Guy,
and that's rich, but...
Order up.
FIERI:
These days, Sammy's wife Ann and
son Tony are running the joint.
More coffee, anybody?
FIERI:
And Tony's making sure
his dad's legacy is living on,
especially in the kitchen.
TONY:
This is Larry's Volcano.
First, we're gonna fry up
our homemade potatoes,
some little diced onions on top.
And homemade Italian sausage.
A customer came in, and he asked
if he could have homemade
Italian baskets and gravy,
and then he started to say,
"Could I also throw
on this and this?"
His name was Larry,
and my dad goes,
"Okay, what would you
like it to be called?"
And he's like, "Volcano."
This is our freshly
toasted biscuit.
Throw the sausage on top.
Our home-style diced potatoes.
A sharp cheddar kind of adds
a little bit of bite with it.
We'll throw down one egg.
We're gonna smother our
home-style potatoes, biscuits,
and sausage with our gravy.
And then, we'll top it off
with the style of egg
that they would like.
Larry's Volcano.
Order.
WOMAN: Larry's Volcano literally
looks like a volcano.
When you cut into it, the yolk
just drips all over like lava.
♪♪
[ Speaks Italian ]
These came from
Nanu Nanu.
Hey, Nanu Nanu.
"Mork and Mindy."
Grandma and grandpa.
Grandma and grandpa,
that's what I thought.
TONY:
The camaraderie that they were
able to pick up,
it looked like they were best
friends for years and years.
I'm getting you
a pepper grinder, Sammy.
That's it.
I'd love one, Guy.
A couple months later,
Guy sent us a pepper grinder
that my dad always wanted,
and it was personalized
"Sammy Tomato."
[ Speaks with mouthful ]
Thank you.
Being on "Triple D" meant
to my dad that he made it,
and I think that
he will be proud
to where we continue to take
the restaurant that he started.
I think that
you're the real deal, man.
-Thank you, man.
-This is good stuff, brother.
See you.
And the "Triple D" nation
is so proud of you, Tony,
for keeping your dad's memory
and recipes alive.
It's characters like him that
keep me going back for more.
Like the maven of meatballs
spread the taste of Philly
all over Salt Lake.
The Piazza family in Arizona
serving up pizza and pasta
with a big side
of personality.
Plus, of course,
Sammy Tomatohead,
whose family is still kicking it
old school in Omaha.
And we'll keep traveling
the country,
checking in on more
"Triple D" nation.
See you next week.
Well, don't let that brud get --
Don't let that butter...
[ Speaks gibberish ]
Don't let that bre--
Never mind.
If you can't deliver the line
on the third time...