You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that place
you went to in that one town
"that served that one dish,
how are they doing after
'Triple D'"? You know what?
I don't know.
Let's check it out.
This is "Triple D Nation."
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out, it was only
the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
That's awesome.
...it's what's
on the inside that counts.
Like in Ashland, Oregon.
'Sup, bro.
A sandwich joint that you've
never seen on "Triple D"...
This is, like,
sandwich revolution.
...only here on
"Triple D Nation."
More meat juice!
And...
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
...a wood fired
oven working overtime...
I am so cutting the line
and coming back tomorrow.
...cooking up killer calamari
in Eureka, California.
Turn off the cameras,
close the doors,
get some wine, make some more.
Plus, in Denver, Colorado...
Tell me.
-Are you ready?
-Aye!
...the Empress of Empanadas
is laying down the law...
-The authentic one.
-Oh.
...on classic
Argentinean cooking.
-Little more than like.
-Aw.
GUY: Old friends, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
That's all right here, right now
on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
[ Bell dings ]
Typically in my world,
"Triple D" chefs end
up on "Triple G,"
"Guy's Grocery Games"...
Tonight on "Triple G."
-Guy!
[ Blender whirs ]
...but not at this place.
No, this is a two-time
"Triple G" competitor...
Sup, bro.
...that happens to have
a restaurant here
in Ashland, Oregon.
She opened her restaurant
because she misses
her food from Chicago.
There's only one Chef Mel
and this is Sammich.
♪♪
WOMAN:
The food here is amazing.
Everything is natural
and unique.
You can't get a sandwich
like this anywhere else.
Melissa knows what's right
when it comes to a sandwich.
Ba-da-bing, ba-da-boom.
I love Melissa.
She's just full of heart,
and it all shows up in her food.
GUY: That's Melissa McMillan,
AKA Chef Mel.
So when I tell you that there is
only one Chef Mel,
all you have to do is watch
"Triple G"
and know why she's been
on the show twice.
She's a superstar.
Oh, baby. The zombie sauce.
This is delicious.
From a flavor perspective,
Melissa is the bomb.
Thank you.
You know, when you go on
"Guy's Grocery Games",
it's his rules, his food,
it's his deal.
You don't need three bell
peppers, there's no way.
MEL: I must have done something
right there that I can get him
to come and see my deal.
-So you put it up here --
-Yeah.
And then just give it the...
-You got to --
-Oh, huh?
...a little more muscle.
Is it supposed to hit the --
well, I don't know.
It is supposed
to ring the bell?
[ Bell dings ]
Yeah. What do we have here?
All right, this is
the Chicago Italian beef.
So when we do the beef,
we season our roast
with salt, pepper,
Italian seasoning.
Then we roast it, and it
finishes in this beef juice.
Just cooking down beef
and taking the drippings
from the roast.
Then we do bell peppers.
We get a nice steam
and a nice sear on 'em.
And then before we build
the sandwich,
we drop them in the pot
with the meat juice
'cause what's better
than stuff soaked in meat juice?
Then we grab our giardiniera,
most famous condiment
in Chicago.
Our giardiniera has jalapeños,
serranos, green bells,
red bells, carrots, celery.
And then, your peppers.
All right. More meat juice!
There you go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
-The wetter the better.
-It's wet.
-It's wet now.
-Wetter.
Wait 'till you come
back on the show,
you start bossing me
around like that.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
This is phenomenal.
I mean,
this is really dynamite.
Thank you.
The meat's tender,
the giardiniera's crispy,
it's got great flavor, it's not
overpowering the sandwich,
the bread is just enough
to hold the sandwich together,
the side jus.
Meat juice, chef.
I'm not French.
-I'm calling it jus.
-[ Laughs ]
Chicago Italian beef.
You start with a crispy bun,
the giardiniera's got
some spice to it,
you've got the beef and all
of the wonderful peppers,
and if you don't do it wet,
you're doing it wrong.
♪♪
Chef, this is
a family restaurant.
-Is that how it works?
-We share stuff here.
Okay. I like that.
-Yeah.
-I'm down with it.
-[ Laughs ]
-What's next?
This is the Timmy Mac, it's
after my little brother, Timmy.
So what's the rundown?
What do we have?
We have the same
house-roasted beef,
but instead it's seared
on a flat top
so it gets a little knotty
and crispy.
And onions, and then
you've got American cheese,
more mayo than you would
put on it at home, lettuce,
and meat juice.
Okay, so a cross between
a Philly cheesesteak --
-No, no, no, no, no.
-No?
Oh, no.
-Cheese and meat.
-It's a Chicago cheesesteak.
I'm so sorry.
♪♪
Yeah!
That's awesome.
With the extra acid that you get
from this lettuce salad,
and a little bit
of the extra fat
that you're getting
from the cheese,
all mixed together
with that tender roast beef,
it's a cross between a po'boy,
meets a cheesesteak,
meets a Chicago Italian beef,
all in one.
This is, like,
sandwich revolution.
Thanks, dude.
It's got this cheesy,
melty goodness
in the middle of the meat.
I thought I was only gonna
eat half of it,
but I ate the whole thing.
♪♪
Hi, first time to Sammich?
Oh, congratulations.
It's Thursday, everybody
eats free on Thursday.
What? No!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Next up, what do we got?
House-made pastrami,
it's Montreal-style.
So it's gonna be smokier
and fattier than New York style.
-With the brisket, though?
-Yes, chef.
MEL: I'm very serious
about my brisket
that I turn into pastrami.
Step 1, we brine it.
Step 2, is we smoke it.
And then after that, we're gonna
steam it so it's not chewy.
Comes traditional the way
it was made in Romania.
Russian, Swiss, pastrami,
coleslaw -- that's it.
What are you crusting it in?
Coriander, black pepper,
juniper berries,
star anise, chili flakes.
-Mmm!
Star anise, I like that.
The Pastrami Zombie sandwich,
you can see, like,
the caramelization
on the ends of it,
and it's cut really
nice and thick.
It's really good.
Now if you get it with Swiss,
can you just get straight-up
pastrami and Swiss on whatever
you want without slaw?
-No.
-You can't?
You can't do
whatever you want here.
-You can't do whatever you want?
-No.
-It comes the way you make it.
-Yup.
So if they just want
a pastrami and Swiss...
If they've tried it at least
twice the way I make it,
then I'll do it
the way they want it.
♪♪
Thanks a lot
for coming to Sammich.
Take care.
-So, am I hired?
-No.
-[ Laughs ]
♪♪
I love how Mel's always
doing things her way.
And Mel, you sure you wouldn't
want to hire one of
the members of my team?
Come on.
Now, coming up
in Northern California...
We're in
the wood fired oven club.
...a chef revving up his oven...
How hot is this thing?
...and taking it into overdrive.
We can't hang out together.
Mm!
So I grew up in Humboldt County,
California.
And last time I was here
for "Triple D,"
my mom recommended this joint
with a wood fire pizza
oven and seafood.
It was off the chain.
Now, since then,
they've expanded their menu
and their real estate.
And my mom is still raving
about the joint.
This is Brick & Fire.
Hot food on 14.
When I came in and ate here,
I saw that Guy had come
through with the show,
and I've been loving
the place since then.
WOMAN: Foodies come here.
They know that this
is the place to eat.
I think that the brick oven
is the centerpiece
of this restaurant.
It takes up a lot
of the kitchen,
but it's worth
the square footage
because of the beautiful
food it produces.
GUY: I first came in
and met owner Jim Hughes
because of my mom Penny.
But I kept coming back
because of that wood-fired oven.
There's wood-fired ovens,
and then there are
wood-fired ovens.
Wood-fired ovens.
And it's awesome!
Oh, don't get me.
I go -- I...
I know, I know, I know.
We're in the wood-fired
oven club.
You got to love that
he's cooking everything out of
this oven --
lasagna, beef, even oysters.
Here we go.
♪♪
-[ Speaks indistinctly ]
Now, is that an oyster?
So you roast them, they're
in their natural juice,
they just cooked a little bit.
I mean this isn't quite oyster,
this is like a fried oyster.
This is just the cross between,
it's like oyster al dente.
I mean, he tasted that
and appreciated it,
and gave me some of his
Guy exclamations. [ Laughs ]
We can't hang out together.
Ah.
So, what are we on to now?
Now we're gonna do
the wild mushroom cobbler.
First, we're gonna do
is soaking
some dried wild mushrooms --
porcini, chanterelle, morels in
there, and some dried shiitakes.
While that's working,
what's up?
chopped shallots, and onions.
-Fresh oyster.
-Yeah.
Creminis.
This is mushroom mayhem.
And then, just for
some more mushroom,
we take dried porcini mushrooms,
put them in the coffee grinder.
Yes.
There we go.
Little heavy cream.
Excellent.
Just fill up a ramekin
with some nice, hot mushrooms,
biscuit, a little parm.
-And into the magic oven?
-Yeah.
How hot is this thing?
Well, it starts at a bout 700.
Thousand degrees.
Yeah. [ Whistles ]
♪♪
That is outstanding.
The depth of the oyster
and the chanterelle
and portobello,
and the cremini,
it goes on and on.
That's an appetizer?
That's an appetizer.
[ Utensil thuds ]
It was really cool how people
from all over the country
follow their stomachs to
the places that Guy's visited.
Luckily, it gave me
the chance to expand.
I opened up this great little
wine bar two doors down.
The servers actually
put it on plates
and walk it two doors down
because,
not only is it the name
of the establishment,
that's where it is.
GUY:
That includes this seasonal pie,
the spicy peach pizza.
The farmer's market
has some great peaches
out of Willow Creek.
So we built a pizza around this.
Put down our goat
cheese crème fraîche,
these nice ripe summer peaches,
then our house-cured pancetta,
a sprinkle of red onion...
GUY: And the real kicker...
...fresh jalapeños,
and our asiago cheese blend.
And into the brick oven.
♪♪
Spicy peach pizza on 14.
MAN: Great combination of spices
and sweet.
And the crust here is by far
the best in the county.
How do you describe the menu
at Brick & Fire?
It's built around, really all
the local ingredients
that I can come across.
You know, up here
in Humboldt County
we're blessed
with such a variety of --
You're talking about
the bounty of the county.
...wild food, farm foods,
you know,
we have a beautiful,
clean ocean out there.
GUY: Which is the inspiration
for his grilled calamari
with shrimp and leek stuffing.
We're gonna be sautéing
the shrimp mixture
and then butter and lemon,
a little salt and pepper,
breadcrumbs, parsley.
We source the calamari
from the Monterey Bay.
We fill that with
the shrimp mixture.
And when it grills,
the body shrinks a little bit.
You don't want to grill it
too long,
it'll get a little too tough.
Calamari up on 16.
The calamari is beautiful.
Feels like you get
all the local flavors.
There's not
a rubbery molecule in it.
This calamari is delicious.
Chef, awesome job.
-Really, Jimmy, you are --
-Thank you.
I am so glad I got to know
who you are
because I am so cutting the line
and coming back tomorrow.
-Awesome.
-And tonight.
-And I'm not leaving.
-[ Chuckles ]
Turn off the cameras,
close the doors,
get some wine,
make some more.
♪♪
Now that's my kind of chef,
firing up everything
from appetizers to desserts
in a wood-fired oven.
Next up...
That's awesome.
...we're headed to Denver,
Colorado...
-Now we make the empanadas,
-Let's do empanadas. Vamos.
GUY:
...with this Argentinean chef.
Tarta. [ Laughs ]
There's not that many
"R"s in it, really.
...has mastered the art
of the empanada assembly line.
-Little more than like.
-Aw.
Now, not too long ago,
I met the chef
who was cranking out
1,500 empanadas a day
at her cool
little corner spot.
And now, she's about
to open her fourth joint.
I'll call that
an empanada empire.
This is Maria Empanada.
♪♪
Have a good day.
We found out about this place
on "Triple D."
I just love how they display
their food
when you first walk in.
You really feel like you've had
an experience of Argentina --
the people, as well
as the atmosphere, and the food.
GUY: And when I first met owner
Lorena Cantarovici,
her passion for food...
[ Speaking Spanish ]
GUY: ...and Argentina
was front and center.
And how did the empanada
empire start?
Because I miss it a lot,
and I didn't find any empanada
here in Denver
so I need to make it.
It doesn't even matter
what she's talking about,
all of a sudden
in became dramatic.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Then what happened?
You want to really hear
what happened?
Oh. Yes, I do. Tell me!
-Are you ready?
-Aye!
[ Laughter ]
We just decided that
the business grow a lot,
and we needed to move.
[ Laughter ]
We should do
a Latino novella together.
Guy, call me if you need me.
-So...
-We're going to make the dough.
And we will put some salt here.
-Baking powder.
-And the margarine.
-All purpose flour?
-Yes.
Eggs, and water.
And we have it right here.
How many pounds of dough
do you make a day?
Oh, I don't have any idea.
I don't have any idea.
[ Mumbles indistinctly ]
Okay.
Grab the baby,
and we put it here.
What'd you just say?
-My baby.
-All right.
And then we take it
to la machina.
So this is
the empanada express?
Yes.
[ Machine whirring ]
You like it? [ Laughs ]
That's awesome.
And we do like this.
And that's empanada dough.
So we made the dough, and now
we're going to make the...
Filling.
So we glaze some onions.
We have red peppers.
-Okay, next?
-Ground beef.
We gonna season this at all,
or are you just gonna
sit there and stir?
Yes, oh, you make me forget.
-I made you forget.
-You talk a lot.
-Okay.
-I talk a lot?
[ Laughter ]
Yeah, look at this.
Pepper, crushed red pepper.
-Cumino.
-Muy bien.
And this is pimenton,
Spanish paprika.
-Not spicy?
-No spicy.
Now we make the empanadas.
Let's do empanadas, vamos.
We put some olives, some of
the filling that we made.
♪♪
So each one
gets this fold over?
Yes.
375, 10, to 12 minutes.
So empanadas are ready.
I was thinking that maybe
he would not like it.
♪♪
Do you like it?
Little more than like.
Aw. I like you, too.
It's nice, it's light.
Little flavor,
little crust -- simple.
Yes.
So you don't only do
empanadas, though.
-No.
-What else do you do?
-Tartas.
Tartas.
He was laughing for me
because I was rolling my tongue
like I will never stop.
Tarta. [ Laughs ]
There's not that many R's
in it, really.
So roasted veggies.
And now some basil.
-Basil, all right.
-Yes.
And the green onions.
-And look at the color here.
-Beautiful.
-Isn't that great?
Now we knead the dough.
And then we put
some cream cheese.
Cream cheese is Argentinean.
-Queso creama, claro!
-Queso creama!
Queso creama!
♪♪
That reminds me
of almost like a calzone.
Nice, bright,
fresh vegetables.
You're able to eat it almost
like you're eating a sandwich.
People will dig it.
But that's not the only thing
she's serving by the slice.
One gallega.
Check out this newcomer,
the gallega.
We are going to combine tuna
with tomato sauce
and the hard boiled eggs.
We put all the feeling --
[ Record needle scratches ]
...filling. [ Laughs ]
There are a few words
that I can't even say
still in English.
And now we are going
to cover this,
and we are going
to make the design.
It's going to look beautiful.
This is a perfect gallega.
There's lots of layers of flavor
that all go really,
really well together.
There's a lot of tuna.
It's a meal.
GUY: And no meal is complete
without dessert.
So coming up...
-Ah-da-da-da-da no.
-Ah-aye-aye-aye.
GUY: Lorena's latest way
to satisfy your sweet tooth.
-Thank you.
-Very good.
Welcome back "Triple D" here
in Denver, Colorado,
hanging out with
the empanada Princess
with her empanada empire,
and we are at Maria Empanada.
Now the first time I was there,
Lorena was churning out
about a dozen
different empanadas.
But these days, she's added
a few more...
If you look in the dictionary
under empanada,
that's what it looks like.
...which includes this killer
combo, the chicken chimichurri.
[ Record needle scratches ]
Guy, chimichurri.
-Chimichurri.
-Si.
Parsley, red pepper.
-Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-What, what, what, what?
This is chimichurri
with red pepper?
It's chimichur --
-The authentic one.
-Oh.
[ Tiger growls ]
I'm trying to be
very Argentinean here.
-Pimenton.
-Pimenton, si.
Okay.
Then we have crushed
red pepper.
-Ah-da-da-da-da no.
-Aye, aye, aye.
-Vinegar, oregano --
-Si, si.
...and olive oil.
You got to have a chimichurri.
Herbaceous, a little bit
of heat, kinda sweet.
-Thank you.
-Very good.
So we are going to mix
chimichurri with the chicken,
and we will cook this
for 10 minutes approximately.
Now we can make the empanadas.
♪♪
One chicken chimichurri.
You get that delicious bite
of chimichurri,
that nice little spice
in there,
and then the chicken
which is super savory
and kind of melts in your mouth
as you eat it.
Excellent.
It's a variation on
their standard chicken.
And their chimichurri
is very authentic.
One, two, three, four,
five, six.
Seven. [ Laughs ]
We opened two more locations
here in the Denver area,
and now we are building
our fourth location.
The variety of menu items
has expanded so dramatically,
which is so much fun.
GUY: And a little sweet.
Now, with the dough,
we are ready
to make
our strawberry ala crema.
This is cream cheese
with sugar and ginger,
and we mix it with strawberry.
And we make it
like a little heart.
We cook at 400 for 10 minutes.
SERVER:
Strawberry ala cremas.
This thing is like a little
toaster strudel for,
like, the 21st century.
It is delicious and amazing --
has so many flavors.
It's to die for.
♪♪
When people ask me about
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives,"
and they're like,
"What are the places"?
This is it.
You got a character, you got
a story, and you got great food.
LORENA: He started talking
about my story.
And then goosebumps all around.
All the passion that I put
in my food is being recognized.
-Thank you.
-Well done, girl.
Thank you.
Watch out, she's opening
one near you soon.
♪♪
What a story.
And meeting people passionate
about their food
is what "Triple D" is all about.
So whether it's the Empanada
Empress of the Rocky Mountains,
the brick oven lovin' chef
firing up things
near my hometown,
or the sandwich slayer bringing
Chi Town flavors to Oregon --
they're all part
of the Triple D Nation.
And we got plenty
more stories to tell.
We'll see you next time.
You have a bunch of equipment
from where?
[ Laughs ]
My refrigerators are
from an old blood bank.
[ Laughs ]
We cleaned them really well,
I swear.