Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins,
and dives!
This trip...
Let the games begin.
...we're taking a big bite
out of the Big Easy...
36 to go, please.
...on this tasty tour
of New Orleans.
This is a show-stopper.
We've got prime time
po' boys...
Bro, that is gangster.
...seafood with a spin.
Boom, there it is.
...and the bomb butcher...
That's outstanding.
...putting a twisted
take on local flavors.
Let's make our ticket
to Flavortown,
because we're going to get
kicked out of New Orleans,
that's for sure.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D"!
♪♪
So, I'm here for
a special edition
of "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
Now, typically, in an episode,
we'll go to different cities,
different states, and sometimes
different countries.
But no, this episode
is all about the great city
of New Orleans.
Why?
Because if I have one more
friend say, "Hey, listen.
I'm going to New Orleans,
where do I eat?"
Well, this is your episode.
So, to kick things off,
we're here in an area
known as Mid-City
to check out a joint
where two chefs have come
together to form a restaurant
where they're -- let's see -
they're butchering it,
they're brining it,
they're stuffing it,
they're smoking it,
and they're serving it.
This is Piece of Meat.
♪♪
Your charcuterie barn.
Piece of Meat
has the best meat in town.
They're the only ones around.
No one does it like them.
This is it.
The best.
Pastrami's up.
It's a full-service butcher shop
and restaurant.
FIERI: Which adds up
to co-owners Leighann Smith
and Daniel Jackson
becoming multi-tasking pros.
So, you've got
a butcher shop...
-Yeah.
-Yep.
-...smoke shop...
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
-...charcuterie...
-Yeah.
-...a restaurant...
...a wholesaler.
We basically tried to fit as
many concepts as we possibly
could into
a 900 square-foot space.
It's like
a big playground.
WOMAN: Everything has sort of
a New Orleans feel,
but it's mixed together in fun
ways, like the boudin egg rolls.
Boudin egg rolls.
WOMAN #2: Boudin is
a sausage stuffed with rice
traditional to
the Louisiana area.
And then, wrap it around
pepper jack cheese,
and then,
fry it with dough.
One of the most amazing vehicles
I've seen for boudin.
Okay, you're going to get
kicked out of New Orleans.
So, we're taking this
whole hindquarter.
SMITH: Yeah.
That's like music.
Going whole animal is just about
as cool as it comes.
It makes it easier,
'cause you have all the
different cuts that you need.
All right.
Pork butt's broken down.
So, the spice mix is salt,
black pepper, white pepper,
a little bit of dry thyme,
some pig salt...
-Okay.
-...smoked paprika, and cayenne.
We put the liver in
with the pork.
Chicken livers.
Then, we put jalepeños in there,
poblanos,
celery, garlic,
and some onions.
Add our spice mix.
-Okay.
You let this sit
for 24 hours.
-Really?
-So it all gets into the pork.
Where do you
keep everything?
Very organized.
Evidently.
We just add
a tiny bit of water,
and then we braise it for about
three and a half hours.
-That looks fantastic.
-Isn't it lovely?
Right into the mixer.
Load the rice.
-I love white rice.
Green onions, chicharon,
add the braising liquid back in.
My favorite recipes are when
you got to eyeball it like this.
All right, chef, let's make
our ticket to Flavortown,
because we're going to get
kicked out of New Orleans.
All right. So, we take --
The sacred boudin.
Yeah. And we take a piece
of pepper jack cheese.
We just roll them up.
Straight to the deep fryer.
-Right to the health tank.
-Exactly.
-There we go.
So, there they are.
The abomination
on a little tray.
You have the nice,
melty cheese.
I want to fill out a time
capsule for my heart.
Yeah, be sure to call
in the defibrillator.
Sriracha mayonnaise.
And there you go, boss.
I'm surprised, here
at Piece of Meat,
that you don't sell
these as earrings.
Yeah.
You know
what that does?
That wrecks boudin for me
from now on.
Yeah.
that's the goal.
Because boudin in regular casing
is like, "Hey."
This,
in crunchy casing...
We can really get texture
out of it.
It's not soggy and wet.
There's just a touch of heat,
all that fantastic pork flavor.
You're getting enough
of the vegetable flavor
with that green onion
that's coming through.
And then, the creaminess
of the cheese --
thanks a lot!
That's fantastic.
-Awesome.
-Uh, 36 to go, please.
Boudin egg rolls are up.
It's my favorite
local dish.
It's just melt-in-your-mouth
deliciousness.
We've got
six more chickens.
Smoking over there.
You can watch
the sausage being made,
and it's a really cool
kind of open environment.
They'll explain it
to you.
They'll tell you where you meat
is coming from.
It's fun to watch them
enjoy what they do.
FIERI: And it's not
their first rodeo,
'cause these culinary partners
joined forces
after they met working
at another joint in town.
We realized that
I'm a psychopath,
and he's really
well-balanced,
and we work
really well together.
Huh.
Teamwork,
that's it!
You know they're cooking,
you know you're going to get
some really
spectacular food.
So, if it's this good on
our first swing of the bat,
what are we
gonna do next?
-We're going to make a --
-Hang on, hang on.
So, the girl who's blowing out
boudin sausage
in a way
we've never seen.
When we come back, it's gonna be
something else great.
Let me just focus
as I eat these.
Think up what
we're cooking next.
Okay.
I'm a lot less nervous than
I thought I was going to be.
You're not nearly
as cool
as I thought you were
going to be, but...
Well, that's usually
what everybody says.
Just kidding.
You're lovely.
"Wow. What a dumpling
that guy is."
So, we're hanging out
in New Orleans at Piece of Meat.
I come to Piece of Meat
because it's the local butcher.
I'm gonna de-bone
a couple.
-Ooh.
-Mm, fancy.
We come here, sometimes,
for lunch.
I'll have the sandwich.
-Bologna sandwich up.
The bologna sandwich
is famous.
It's definitely an old classic
with a new twist on it.
All right, we're making bologna,
and we use the pork shoulder.
The lean meat in here
is what we dice and brine.
Okay.
And the rest of it has
the appropriate amount of fat
for the grind that we use to
make the farce for the sausage.
-For the farce?
-Yeah, the grind
for the sausage.
The grind for
the sausage. Okay.
May the farce
be with you.
So, we're basically gonna dice
all this lean meat.
This is going to have
funkin' nuggets?
-Yeah.
-Big pieces of brined meat.
It's gonna stud the inside
of this rustic bologna.
Yeah.
My mouth is starting to water.
So, we make the brine
with molasses.
-Salt?
-Yeah.
-Brown sugar?
-Nailed it.
-White sugar.
-And a little curing salt.
Hot water.
How long are we
gonna brine this?
-Three hours.
-Next up?
Our spice mix starts with salt,
white pepper,
we got coriander...
-Okay.
...pink salt yet again,
ginger, mace, mustard powder,
and dextrose.
Now we have the ground farce
into the mixture.
We add the lean meat,
and then our spice mix,
and then we mix it for about
two or three minutes.
And then, we stuff it.
Let the games begin.
What a pro!
Look at that.
On the stick
burner outside.
-Yep.
-We smoke with oak.
So there's the nice lean meat
pieces, the sausage around it.
♪♪
This is terrible.
I got to go.
Can't hang out
with you anymore.
Loser.
I'm not kidding you.
In the history
of "Triple D"...
Uh-huh?
...that's some of
the best meats
cured, pressed, cased,
something we've had.
Thank you.
Ready for a sandwich?
Yes, I'm ready
for a sandwich.
So, we start with
an onion bun
from a local bakery
in New Orleans.
Mayonnaise down first.
Yes, 'cause mayonnaise
is what I need.
You'll be fine.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Little iceberg lettuce,
'cause it's classy,
the bologna with barbecue sauce
and provolone cheese
What kind of
barbecue sauce?
We make a sweet onion
soy sauce barbecue sauce.
Fried onions.
I'm gonna cut it in half.
Get it.
Just so I can look
a little bit civilized.
♪♪
You're the worst
best friend to have.
Thank you.
You take things
that people love,
and that they know
really well,
and you show them how great
it could have been
for all these years.
That's outstanding.
That little underlying tone
of the molasses
and the brown sugar --
mmm.
Great roll,
onion crunch makes it,
little old-school
mayonnaise,
and iceberg lettuce --
takes you back.
But when you get brined,
tender meat inside of ground,
super-flavorful, textural meat,
you can't beat it.
Bologna sandwich.
I'm not even
a fan of bologna,
but I come here
just for this sandwich.
Best bologna I've ever had
in my life.
SMITH: Plating ribs.
We're in a city full
of restaurants,
and this is one of the ones
you want to come back to over,
and over
and over again.
You make 900 square-feet
taste like 9,000 square-feet.
-Thank you.
-You've got the personality,
you've got the attitude,
you've got the energy.
You have the lack
of self-control.
You do whatever
you want to do.
You're dangerous, woman.
[ Laughs ]
Up next, a funky-fresh
seafood spot...
I mean, that's legit.
That's really legit.
...where cuisine
and crazy creativity...
You have got a big imagination,
my friend.
...collide.
That looks like a roadside
in Flavortown right there.
♪♪
So, on the next stop of this
"Triple D" New Orleans tour,
here we are
in the city of Harahan.
Now, it's about 20 minutes
from downtown New Orleans,
and about 10 minutes away
from the River Shack Tavern
that we shot
just years ago.
Now, when you drive
by this place,
first thing you can say is,
"Oh, hey, a shrimp
and po' boy joint."
Don't judge a book by its cover
for sure on this one,
because they've got
chapters of culinary good
that you've just
got to read about.
This is Seither's Seafood.
I got a Peepaw salad.
It's where people that are
from New Orleans go eat.
One boiled
seafood platter.
All your favorite
New Orleans-style dishes
done in Jason's way.
-That's Jason Seither...
-Make it snow!
...who grew up in the bayou,
boiling crawfish with his dad
and cooking in the kitchen
with his mom.
I'm respecting
the old-school ingredients,
but I'm just incorporating
my own style into it.
-Here's the volcano.
-A volcano is actually something
that I get almost
every time we come.
It's a lot of
familiar things
presented in a way
you never saw.
The volcano is basically like
an upside-down Asian taco salad.
Oh, you hear about
those every day.
First, we're going to make
the blackening seasoning.
I've got some paprika
right here...
Some pap-a-rika.
...black pepper,
sea salt, parsley flakes,
granulated onion,
granulated garlic,
and then,
the Italian seasoning.
Okay. So, now,
we have the fresh Ahi.
Right.
This is local.
So, if you can't get it fresh,
you just won't be serving it?
-That's exactly right.
-The best attitude.
We'll sear this off.
Next step?
Spicy mayo --
I call it "dragon sauce,"
just to have
a cool name.
-All it is is mayo.
-And sriracha.
I like to add a little bit
of water to it
because when I put it
in the squeeze bottles,
I can, like,
draw with it.
I don't speak Cajun.
That's how you say
"draw with it" in Cajun?
-Draw with it!
-Next?
-The crab salad.
-Okay.
I'm taking this shredded kani
that they use in sushi rolls.
So, this is pollock.
Take some of this sauce --
The Cajun measuring system.
Right?
All right, so, I'm gonna show
you how to make this volcano.
I am on the edge
of my seat.
-Here we go.
-Gorgeous!
Fillet the tuna
around here,
avocados, lettuce
right in the middle.
Put the shrimp
on there,
the spicy mayo that we made,
eel sauce, sriracha.
I'm dizzy.
Take the taco shell,
turn it upside down.
Put some of the
snow crab salad on top,
spicy mayo, eel sauce,
a little bit more sriracha.
And then, I finish it off
with sesame seeds.
So, that right there is
the -- oops -- volcano.
See, it just erupted.
Interesting.
Do you jump on it?
-Yeah.
-Hit it with an elbow.
I mean, you've just
got to go at it.
I was able to build
a bite there, folks.
Right. So, you got, like,
a little nacho right there.
I don't care
what you do with it,
when you serve tuna
that fresh --
I mean, that's legit.
That's really legit.
I'm not a huge sauce guy, but I
think this is a show-stopper.
I mean, people see this come
out, they're going to go, "Wow."
It's like an awesome
little salad.
And it looks cool, too.
Can I go?
Go for it, dude.
All right. Walking in the door,
I got a volcano.
Jason's just sort of
pushed the creative envelope.
WOMAN: Delicious.
And you can feel like you're
eating something special.
When I started off,
it was like a seafood market,
so I got all these
different awesome
connections with
crabs and shrimp.
FIERI:
And he's calling on them all
to build this seafood sculpture.
I have a totem pole.
All of my New Orleans
favorites wrapped into one dish.
It's fresh seafood layer
upon layer upon layer.
It looks like a totem pole with
a crab in the middle of there.
You have got a big imagination,
my friend.
All right. I'm going to show you
how to make the crab stuffing.
Hit it.
Butter, celery,
garlic, onions, peppers,
lump crab meat
fresh out of Lake Ponchartrain,
the claw meat.
And this is the stuffing that
goes inside of the totem pole?
-Right.
-Next in?
I love dust.
Crawfish boil, crab boil.
The blackening seasoning
that we made earlier.
Gumbo fillet --
a little sassafras.
Grab them
sassafras leaves.
Little bit of
the love dust.
You name these things?
-Absolutely.
Blackening seasoning,
water, lemon juice,
bread crumbs, and then --
boom, there's your stuffing.
Boom, there it is.
Now, we're going to get
some soft-shell crabs
ready for
the totem pole.
And I'm a huge
soft-shell crab fan.
When you get a chance
to come down here
and try true soft-shell crab
done the right way --
game changer.
Tons of flavor.
Then, it goes into
the buttermilk.
And then,
into our fish fry.
into the oil.
Eggplant.
-Beautiful.
Let me see
the totem pole.
Here's that crab stuffing
that we just made.
Put a piece of this
fried eggplant on there.
More crab stuffing.
-And this is hot?
-Absolutely.
Got some more of that.
And then, here comes
your soft-shell crab.
More crab stuffing,
more eggplant.
This is a cream sauce,
And then, hold it all together
with this shrimp kebab.
More sauce on that.
And then, we need
some Parmesan cheese.
-Of course we do.
-Put a little greens on there.
You have issues.
Yeah.
Good ones,
but issues.
♪♪
The batter on that crab --
money.
Thank you.
I did not want to like
the crab stuffing,
'cause I've never
heard of it.
And to me, it was just
a crab cake
that didn't get the love
texture on the outside.
But this, right here,
works perfect.
You get this smooth,
creamy texture
with the crunch
of the eggplant --
and a good piece
of eggplant --
and then, you get the gravy.
Then, you get that money bite.
That's like a roadside
in Flavortown right there.
That's getting it done.
The totem pole
is my favorite.
I love the soft-shelled crab.
I love the eggplant.
When I first really started to
learn about Cajun creole cooking
was from this guy
right here.
Kim Gardner, let me hear
what you think.
-That's good.
-There you go.
Kim says it's good,
I'll come here.
I mean, this is a little
funky seafood shack.
Will you expect this
kind of food out of them?
GARDENER: When you look at
this place, you don't.
But I would drive
for this.
I got a hamper,
table nine!
It's our very favorite
restaurant.
Just heavenly goodness all the
way through every time I come.
FIERI:
The way you treat food, and the
imagination you have as a chef,
and the appreciation
you have for fresh seafood --
you're doing a great job, man.
Appreciate it.
Excellent.
Coming up,
another New Orleans gem...
This is on point.
...getting saucy
with their oysters...
We're breaking boundaries
here on "Triple D."
...and going unexpected
with a familiar favorite.
If tater salad wasn't good
enough, we're gonna
fry it for you.
♪♪
So, for our final stop
on this special edition
of "Triple D"
in New Orleans,
we're here to check out
a joint on Tulane.
It started off
as a prank,
and turned out to be
the real deal.
Husband and wife team
making traditional
New Orleans specialties in not
such a traditional manner.
This is
Avery's on Tulane.
Buffalo shrimp
po' boy.
Whenever I have people in
from out of town,
I always take them here,
'cause it's the best
New Orleans cuisine.
Stuffed artichoke balls
with crawfish sauce.
I came here one time,
and I was completely hooked.
FIERI: But at one point
for Justin Pitard
and his wife, Christy,
the very idea of opening
this joint was, well, laughable.
Now, how did you
two end up here?
Kind of as
a practical joke.
She said she wanted
to open a restaurant.
A practical joke is
a restaurant opening?
I was a
property manager,
and this was one of
the properties I managed.
It was destroyed.
Nothing in there?
Unh-unh.
It was bad.
I told her that it was
her "new restaurant."
She called my bluff.
FIERI:
And they turned that prank
into a seriously funky joint.
You go into their variations
on the basic New Orleans menu,
like your oysters
Rockefeller po' boy.
Oysters Rockefeller
po' boy.
This po' boy
is delicious.
They fry the oysters,
and they top it with a creamy
Parmesan and spinach sauce.
It's definitely like
a mother's touch.
What are we making?
PITARD: We're making our
oysters Rockefeller sauce.
-All right. Let's see it.
-All right.
Butter goes in, onion,
garlic, and is liquor.
We take shots of it,
or do we put it in the pan?
We can take shots.
Yeah, 90 proof,
that's my kind of --
Never opposed.
Little flame on that,
I imagine.
Yes, sir.
Some half and half,
granulated onion,
granulated garlic, white pepper,
and ground thyme.
A little hot sauce.
-Okay.
-Frozen spinach.
Now, people say
"Why frozen spinach?"
It would take that much
fresh spinach to make that work.
I don't even have the space
for that much spinach.
You don't have the spinach
for that much space?
Enough space for
that much spinach.
Enough spinach for that
much space, right.
Let's put the spinach
in there.
He doesn't even have enough
spinach space.
We'll do the Parmesan,
add some bread crumbs.
Oh, I'm going to need
to add a little more
half and half to this.
Well, I'm gonna add a little
of this to my mouth.
That's really good.
All right.
So, we're gonna
make our dredge.
Got it.
Yellow corn flour,
white AP flour,
lemon pepper,
creole seasoning.
All right.
Next?
We're going to bread
and fry our oysters.
Fry them just till you get
a crisp, nice and tender inside?
Yep. Garlic butter
the bread for toasting.
We got some oysters,
some of that Rockefeller sauce,
a little Parmesan,
and she's done.
Mmm.
Bro, that is gangster.
Oysters are
cooked correctly.
Dredge is really nice,
good crunch to it,
The Rockefeller sauce
is spot-on.
Mmm.
The crust of the bread
just holds it together --
just becomes
the foil.
If oyster Rockefeller is going
to be made into a po' boy,
it better be made like this.
Dude, this is on point.
-Awesome.
-Oysters Rockefeller po' boy.
The sandwich is fresh.
The sauce on top is creamy,
and has great flavor.
-So, have you ever
had an oyster?
-No.
If you're gonna try
an oyster,
this is the one
you've got to try.
I'll try a tiny,
little piece of it.
This is so outside
of my wheelhouse.
We're breaking boundaries
here on "Triple D."
It's crunchy. It's delicious.
Great depth of flavor.
Oh, that's terrific.
Seafood gumbo!
Where do you guys
get your seafood from?
PITARD: From a multitude
of different locations.
That's the name
of the place?
We'll get our catfish
and alligator from one place --
[ Whistles ]
Time out. You guys
do enough alligator
that you have a specific
alligator purveyor?
-Yep.
-You deep-fry the alligator?
-What don't we deep-fry?
Salad?
No. We deep-fry potato salad.
The fried potato salad
is like a baked potato balled up
and deep-fried,
with delicious,
homemade horseradish
cream sauce.
If I didn't have enough
fried gator in my diet,
I'm going to have
fried potato salad.
All right. Let me see it.
We'll put our creole
seasoning in, roasted potatoes.
So, those are
gonna boil down.
Yep, And then,
we'll cool them.
Add some chopped bacon,
cheddar,
diced pickles, diced onions,
bell pepper...
Well, I like that your
dragging the potato salad
through the garden.
...celery, green onion,
some sour cream...
-You want this egg?
-Sure.
Hot sauce.
We're mashing it up.
-Okay.
We'll add some creole seasoning
to the bread crumbs.
See the egg wash
that I diligently did.
Thank you for that.
If tater salad
wasn't good enough,
we're gonna
fry it for you.
Old shoe, bring it down.
We'll fry it for you.
We fried Toby Keith's
guitar here.
Oh, whoa, whoa!
What did you just do
to my fried potato?
If you put it in the fryer,
and you don't have that,
it won't heat
all the way through.
-All right.
-Horseradish cream sauce.
So, we've got our
fried potato salad.
I'm gonna make a little
signature "A" right on top.
Oh, hi,
cake decorator.
Green onion, a little
crushed red pepper.
Not bad with
the cake decorating.
Yeah, I've gotten
pretty good at it.
That exceeded my expectations
by about 100%.
Awesome.
You don't have big chunks
of potato,
so you have a nice creaminess
all the way through it.
The kicker is the warm,
crunchy veg --
the celery and the onion
and the bell pepper.
Right amount of binder,
right amount of breading.
Not heavy, not oily.
And then, rocking it with a
bunch of horseradish in there.
Oh, yeah.
But it's supporting it,
because you've got
a lot of sweet coming
through, here, from the fry.
I officially, 100%,
am ripping that off.
I don't know what to say
about that, Guy.
You say
"Thank you very much."
Thank you.
Fried potato salad.
Absolutely perfect.
MAN: It's cheesy. It's crunchy.
it has this zesty sauce,
almost like
a thousand island
with a 10,000%
kick to it.
Muffuletta egg rolls,
please.
Avery's just kind of
switches it up,
and adds some
extra flavor.
The best restaurant
I've ever eaten at.
Good job, brother.
Watch out for this guy.
Your waistband's
gonna increase.
So, that's what
I'm talking about --
oysters Rockefeller
po' boy,
deep fried potato salad.
Does it get any better?
Listen.
That's it for this trip.
But don't you worry,
there's funky joints
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
-What happened there?
-I've never even had --
well, I --
-You've never even had a what?
-Avocado.
Did you see the look?