Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Stack 'em up.
...we're diggin' into comfort...
Excellent.
...that goes way
beyond Grandma's cookbook.
I want to order 100 of these.
We're talking Tex-Mex meat
in Austin...
That's legit.
I mean, like, legit, bro.
...pumped-up pub grub
in Salt Lake...
Delicious.
Don't judge.
...and in Atlanta...
Come on, now.
...my sister
from another mister...
Someone didn't send
the memo.
...servin' up soul with a spin.
The potlicker.
There you go.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So, think about every time
you go on vacation
and you try great food,
or think if you were
a flight attendant
and you flew all over the world,
and you got to taste
all this incredible food.
Think if you took
all that information
and came back
and opened your own restaurant.
I've got a place
where you can taste
those traveling experiences.
If you're in Atlanta, Georgia,
you've got to check out
Twisted Soul.
Portobello stack
with dirty-rice orzo.
It's not necessarily
your regular soul food.
Candied salmon-belly bacon.
I come here just to get
a bit of heaven.
FIERI: And the culinary angel
is Deborah Vantrece,
who took off from being
a flight attendant
to landing her own restaurant.
Someone didn't send
the memo.
We can't have two bleach blondes
in this show.
Although, it looks
better on you.
WOMAN:
Deborah has taken ideas from
her travels around the world
and created something unique.
We're gonna do
a little fusion soul food.
Is that what the restaurant
is about, is soul food?
Yeah.
It's globally inspired.
'Cause in my opinion,
all cultures have a soul food.
You can feel the East
and the West...
the North and the South.
Southern seafood Louie.
The Southern seafood Louie
is so amazing, so rich.
The crab, the shrimp...
everything
is perfectly seasoned.
So, we're gonna do a little play
on the little crab Louie salads.
You know,
the Southern belles down here
used to do that
at the tea parties.
I've never been to
a tea party.
I've been to a kegger.
-Nah. Tea party.
-Tea party is different?
-Yeah.
So, first thing, the roasted
corn vinaigrette that goes
on the seafood
Southern Louie salad.
Gotcha.
All right.
A little olive-oil blend.
Some onions.
And red bell pepper.
Fresh corn.
Sautée this up a bit.
So this is some
apple-cider olive oil.
Cilantro.
Garlic powder.
Seasoning salt.
Onion powder.
-Next up?
Hoecakes.
Don't you say --
-Now wait a second.
I don't want to go out there
into Flavortown
and say it the wrong way.
So how would one say
what we're gonna make next?
-A hoecake.
-Hoecakes.
Did I get it right?
-That's it.
-Hoecakes.
Hoecakes.
Trouble!
[ Laughs ]
We've got
self-rising cornmeal.
Baking soda.
Eggs.
Buttermilk.
Avocados.
I've seen a lot of things
in hoecakes...
I've never seen
the avocado combo.
It is soul food fused
with California.
I got it.
So even the California people
are included.
They've got soul.
-We do.
-Red pepper.
Onion.
Jalapeños.
Oil.
Cilantro.
And that's all she wrote.
What do we have next?
Next, we're gonna
poach the seafood.
A little oil.
Shrimp 'er down.
Shrimp 'er down
a little bit.
Shrimp 'er down.
Lobster down.
Water.
Old Bay.
A little bit
of crab oil?
A little bit of crab oil.
Lump crab.
So a little poach?
Being delicate.
Yep.
And then we let them cool,
and then we'll be ready
for the salad.
You know that I don't often,
on "Triple D," do salads.
A little arugula.
-But this has got attitude.
-A bit of attitude.
Corn relish.
Then the hoecake is what puts it
over the top.
There ya go.
Shrimp.
Add our lobster.
Our lump crab.
Mango vinaigrette.
We're gonna top that
with some micro greens.
It's too pretty to eat.
It is kinda cute, isn't it?
♪♪
I don't typically
like cold seafood.
Because by the time it cooks
and gets held,
it's lost its flavor.
You, on the other hand, you wild
woman, you better blonde...
that is delicious.
-Thank you.
-It's refined.
It's balanced.
You perfectly cooked
the seafood.
Avocado hoecake
is a perfect complement.
There's not many salads
that I would order again.
I would order that every time.
That is too legit to quit.
I'll take that.
Seafood Louie salad.
The seafood Louie is great.
The shrimp is excellent.
I feel I'm having dinner
with my salad.
You've got lobster, you've got
shrimp, you've got crab.
This guy needs no introduction.
He is a "Triple D" OG.
My brother Gus,
from Marietta Diner.
These...
What do you hoecakes?
-Hoecakes.
-Hoecakes? Amazing.
He lives in Atlanta.
What is a hoecake?
A hoecake?
I'm not sure.
Either way, it's delicious.
Honey Jack wings.
I was a flight attendant
with Deborah.
She would make dinner for us
on our flights.
I heard you used to make
some galley gourmet.
Buy ducks in London...
get on there and...
a whole light meal.
-Really?
-Yeah.
WOMAN: Deborah loves people,
and she loves food.
You put those combinations
together...
she really wants to feed people.
-We're in Atlanta.
We're hanging out with my sister
from another mister,
who has way better hair
than me.
When we come back,
what are we gonna make?
Southern
marinated fried chicken.
Fried chicken!
See? I knew it!
You were gonna bait me
in with salad,
and then you were gonna
feed me fried chicken!
-Yeah.
-We'll see you in a bit.
My mom cooked, my Granny cooked,
my aunts cooked.
See?
Makes me...
-I heard it.
-Makes me smile.
I heard the music.
Welcome back. Twisted Soul.
"Triple D."
Atlanta, Georgia...
[Whispers]
and a lot of trouble.
[ Normal voice ]
Started me off with this
"try this little
seafood salad"
and "I'm gonna make this
roasted corn dressing."
Now what are we doing?
Southern marinated
fried chicken.
Yeah. And you know
that means treadmill.
The fried chicken is perfect.
From the crust all the way
through to the bone.
Now we're gonna put some South
in the mouth.
-Now we're going to the South.
-What are we putting with it?
-Sweet-potato apple chutney.
-Let's make it happen.
Start with some butter.
Granny Smith apples.
Lemon juice.
Fingerling sweet potatoes.
We're gonna let
all this goodness
just simmer down together.
Now simmer down, now.
Simmer it down.
Brown sugar.
-A little cinnamon-amon-amon?
A little clove.
A little ginger.
Red peppers.
A little apple cider.
And the pièce de résistance?
A little golden raisins?
-Golden raisins.
-And?
Ginger-infused bourbon.
-Ginger-induced bourbon.
-It's bird time.
Seasoning salt.
Garlic powder.
Onion powder.
And a little black pepper.
And how long is
it gonna hang out?
24 hours.
Dredge it in flour
and house seasoning.
And then right from the jets
to the cast-iron?
-Yep.
-Hit it, don't babysit it.
Now we're ready to assemble
our collard-green roll.
Oil.
Garlic. Cloves.
Onions.
-Peppers and onions galore.
We're gonna mix the greens.
Turn up.
-Turn it up!
Mustard.
Collard.
-Okay.
-Water.
Jalapeños.
And then we've got celery salt,
red-pepper flakes,
a little paprika.
We'll let that baby just simmer
four about two, three hours.
All right, sister.
Let me see it.
All right.
Blanched collard greens.
We try to get the big ones.
Got our cooked greens.
Fold it up and get it done.
And these are gonna sit there
and steam a little bit.
-These are gonna sit there...
-And get a little more tender.
Now we're ready to plate
the Southern marinated
fried chicken.
First, we've got
some mac and cheese.
The collard-green roll.
Sweet-potato apple chutney.
We've got our breast.
Thigh on the side.
And the leg on the other side.
And then...
guess what?
-Come on, now.
Collard-green jus.
The potlicker.
There you go.
The chutney is dynamite.
I love that little golden-raisin
texture at the end.
♪♪
Congratulations on wrecking
collard greens
for the rest of my life.
That's mean.
-It's nasty. That's what it is.
-Ohh. Ohh.
-Yeah.
I want to order 100 of these.
[ Explosion sound effect ]
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
That is good, old-fashioned,
honest fried chicken.
The skin is nice and crispy.
It holds a good crust.
I understand more now...
why it's Twisted Soul,
'cause there's already
a band called
Twisted Sister...
and that's what you are.
You are one twisted sister.
-Thank you.
-Well done.
Southern marinated
fried chicken.
The chicken is juicy but crispy.
The collard-green roll
has a little bite to it.
It's a different twist,
but it's wonderful.
Bacon lettuce green-tomato
sandwich.
If you want a good home-cooked
meal, go to Twisted Soul.
She's the best.
-Well done, my sister.
-Thank you so much.
Watch out for twister sister
at Twisted Soul.
FIERI: Up next...
A roadside round up in Austin...
FIERI:
5 1/2 smokers...
is that enough?
...makin' backyard barbecue
with a Texas twist.
So it's a
ground-brisket-stuffed,
smoked burger?
Yes, sir.
♪♪
So back in the 80's and 90's,
the term "Tex-Mex"
was getting used
all over the United States,
kinda giving it a bad rap.
So I'm here in Austin, Texas,
where a husband-and-wife team
are doing old-school,
backyard Tejano-style,
and they're servin' up what
Tex-Mex is really all about.
This is Valentina's.
Get this food out, please.
It's just great barbecue
with a Tex-Mex feel.
Brisket being sliced up
for Hollywood taco.
It's in a class of its own.
Barbecue platter here for ya.
Miguel is legit Tex-Mex.
FIERI:
Legit an in, Texas born
and raised, learned from pop,
then worked in the food biz
for 17 years, legit.
Now Miguel Vidal
and his wife Modesty
are building their own business,
one smoker at a time.
One, two, three, four...
5 1/2 smokers...
is that enough?
-It's never enough.
People are hungry in Texas.
Explain to me
what Tejano food is.
We take Mexican-American flavors
and we take
backyard-grilling concept,
and we merge them together.
This is what it was
all about in Texas.
Yeah, with my grandparents,
my dad, my mom.
I wanted to represent
what people were doing
in the backyard,
in their home.
When you come to Valentina's,
you can smell the smoke
when you're parking your car
and your mouth starts watering.
I have the La Reina sandwich
for ya.
The La Reina is
a life-changing sandwich.
It's got flavorful pork...
Texas...
it's Spain.
VIDAL: It's it's a sandwich
that was inspired out
of a trip to Barcelona.
I wanted to recreate this
in the Texas version.
So, our we're using our
house dry rub,
which is the base
for everything.
FIERI: Okay.
Salt.
A little bit of paprika.
Chili powder.
Granulated garlic.
Sugar.
-White sugar? Okay.
Cayenne.
And then black pepper.
Then we're gonna season
the pork collar.
Pork collar is awesome.
It's got phenomenal flavor.
We smoke with mesquite wood,
put it on our offset pits,
and it goes for about
four hours.
Okay.
We'll hit it with
the honey-barbecue glaze.
And you make
the honey-barbecue glaze?
Yes, sir.
We have ketchup...
I'll take the hand off.
...mustard.
Little Worcestershire.
Vinegar.
How we doin'
on the black pepper?
-All of it in there.
-All of it?
Granulated garlic.
And this is that seasoning mix
that we made?
-This is our house rub, yep.
-A couple whole onions.
This goes in
the barbecue pit, and...
-You're gonna smoke the sauce?
-Yep.
You see people put liquid smoke
in barbecue sauce a lot.
This right here is
the original way to do it.
We have our barbecue sauce
ready to go.
Take just a little bit of honey,
and add it to it.
So, here we have
our pork collar.
It's served on bolillo bread.
Look at that smoke ring, huh?
Here we have
our honey-barbecue glaze.
Delicious.
Take a little bit
of the onion paste.
You can just spread it
on there nice and light.
When you're working
in these tight quarters,
you've got to be
ready to help out.
Smoked pork collar.
Smoked tomatoes.
Little bit more
of the glaze.
Pickled red onions.
White onions.
House pickles.
-And that's all she wrote.
And that's La Reina.
♪♪
This isn't some
barbecued pork sandwich.
This is elevated barbecue.
Especially
with the pork collar.
I mean, that's just
drivin' it for me.
Smoked tomato.
So, that smaller pit
that you saw?
That takes most
of our vegetables.
-Hang on. Time out.
-Barbecue sauce...
'Cause we have a whole smoker
dedicated to vegetables.
It's for vegetables.
This is far beyond
what you'd expect to get
from roadside barbecue.
That's legit.
I mean, like, legit, bro.
-I appreciate it, man.
La Reina up.
Two times.
The meat is delicious.
It's really tender.
-It's the real deal.
That's my line.
She's taking my line.
It's something you just can't
find anywhere else.
So, you don't have
a brick and mortar,
but what you chose to do
is take a bunch of food trucks,
put them together like
a little village...
My dad had 20 different
smokers in the backyard,
made out of different propane
tanks or whatever, you know?
Seriously?
That's where you got
this caravan of travels.
Hey.
How are y'all doing?
I eat breakfast, lunch,
and dinner
whenever I get the chance here.
Your favorite thing
on the menu?
I'm gonna have to go
with the brisket.
Nobody else compares.
FIERI:
Especially when you could get it
ground up in a burger.
Burgers coming through.
WOMAN: Stuffed with goat cheese,
serrano peppers, and bacon.
Every bite is just a moist,
perfect bite.
So, it's a
ground-brisket-stuffed,
smoked burger?
Yes, sir.
Here's one of our all-natural,
prime briskets.
-Prime black-Angus brisket?
-Yeah.
You're a food trailer
in a driveway.
We're trying to produce
the best that we can.
And that will be all cut up
for grinding...
-Next up?
-We're gonna make our stuffing.
-Okay.
-Queso blanco in here.
Got a little bit
of goat cheese.
-Serranos?
-Then we'll take some bacon.
Gonna make
Tejano Juicy Lucy.
-Jucy Lucy.
-Yeah, I'm sorry.
Jucy Lucy.
Four ounces right there.
Take a chunk of this.
Right in the center.
Seal it up.
We'll hit these
with our dry rub again.
What of the 75 smokers out there
are you gonna put it on?
Maynard.
Each barbecue pit is named after
my favorite band's lead singer.
Oh, no kidding?
So, we have "Maynard" after
the Tool lead singer...
Cornell, Cobain, and Chino,
the singer from the Deftones.
That's awesome. How long does
it go on the smoker?
About 30 minutes each side.
All right.
The smoked burgers.
-They're smoked all right.
-Toss it on here.
Just sear it
for some texture?
Toasted bun.
I'll hit that just for a second.
-Just warm it up?
-House pickles.
-Big burger.
-Caramelized onions.
A couple of bacon pieces
on top.
And hit it
with the hot-mayo mustard.
I don't know if the burger
is big enough.
It's not the size
of my head yet.
Look at that thing.
Wow. Just the right amount
of smoke.
The goat cheese inside of there
offers the perfect tang.
The queso blanco...
it just melts and becomes
the creamy ambassador.
That's...
The creamy ambassador
of Flavortown.
You guys have heard of him,
haven't you? You nailed it.
You got your smoked
stuffed burger here.
WOMAN:
The stuffed burger is delicious.
The smoking...
it just adds a lot of flavor
to it.
MAN:
It's a little bit spicy,
but it's one of those slow burns
that kinda gets addictive.
SERVER: Guac on the fajita.
The best Texas barbecue
I've ever had.
When they see that smokestack
goin', it's like a signal --
come on in
'cause it's open and ready.
I think
what you two are doing,
taking the flavor
and the culture
and the energy
of backyard barbecue
and combining that
with a lot of Texas style
and methods,
you get great food.
Our saying here is
"hecho con amor" --
"made with love."
-Hecho con amor, baby!
Adios.
FIERI: Coming up...
A funky spot in Salt Lake...
You rock.
...mixin' Asian flavors
with American favorites...
It's something you'll never find
at another restaurant.
...to raise the bar on bar food.
The 85-step grilled cheese,
comin' up!
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Salt Lake City, Utah,
to check out a joint that's...
well, it's not really
a restaurant,
and it's not exactly
just a bar,
and they're kinda
doing Asian food,
but it's also mixed
with American food.
You know, these folks
have always just
kinda been in Purgatory.
Hey, wait...
that's a great name.
Check it out.
This is Purgatory.
Curry Loco Moco.
Hands, please.
I don't feel like I can get
the food
I get at Purgatory
anywhere else.
Your taste buds
are just exploding.
Here are your K-pop fries.
The combination of the Asian
with some of the traditional
items that you see at a bar...
it's just unique.
FIERI:
And that American/Asian mash-up
comes from the Asian-American
forces behind it,
owner Diamond Dang
and Chef Hiro Tagai.
Hiro both grew up eating
American food
and grew up eating Asian food,
and so we wanted both
of our cultures combined.
Pork-belly nigiris.
In the window.
The pork-belly nigiri is the
perfect example of that bar food
and the Asian infusion.
It's just adds up to
a pretty incredible flavor.
Pork-belly nigiri.
Exactly -- nigiri like
in the sushi restaurant.
Ten years in the sushi biz.
We're gonna put these
pork bellies into this pot.
-What is this?
-We call it "pork stalk."
Every time we cook
the pork belly, we strain it.
And it just keeps
building flavor?
I mean, it's kind of like
a "mother" in sourdough bread.
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
And a little bit of garlic.
How long is this gonna go,
Chef?
About 90 minutes.
Take it out.
Cool it.
Next step?
The tare,
which is the marinade.
-Okay.
-Some sugar in.
Soy.
Mirin.
Japanese cooking wine,
got it.
Dark soy for color.
And agua.
Boil.
-Got it.
And then we'll dump it
onto the pork belly.
I think it would be
more like a...
[ Imitates glugging ]
Indeed.
Fill this up until
it's completely covered.
[ Laughter ]
We'll let it sit for about
an hour and a half.
Absorb the liquid...
We'll cool it again.
-Mm-hmm.
All right, brother.
Where we at?
We are gonna make
the eel sauce.
Interesting.
We start out with the soy sauce.
Sugar.
The mirin again.
And then some agua.
Chopped onions.
Ginger.
How long we gonna
let this simmer, Chef?
-About two hours to reduce.
-So, it's really syrupy.
-Yep, really syrupy.
-And then we'll strain it.
-Yes, sir.
-What a medial sauce.
That's a first on "Triple D."
I'm gonna cut this pork belly
nice and thin, just like sushi.
-There we go.
-Grab some rice.
I've done that few times.
Press it down and concave it.
Just like we're running
some tuna belly.
-Seaweed.
-Give it a band.
And...boom.
Dude, you cannot take you
out of the sushi line.
Nope. We're gonna grab
some eel sauce.
-Okay.
-Torch it. Torch it. Torch it.
Pickled mustard seeds.
Looking like your
sushi roe.
Some green onion.
Chive.
Raw leeks.
It looks like daikon.
Grab some house-made chili oil.
Boom. It's done.
I asked what you guys made.
You said "bar food."
-Pretty fun.
-Yeah...
♪♪
I owned a sushi restaurant
for quite a few years.
That is one of the most
beautiful plates
of a non-sushi dish
that I've seen.
I mean, that was gorgeous.
-Thank you.
Outstanding flavor.
You took this thing
from scratch.
The sauce, with the chili oil?
With the mustard seed?
You could smear that
on my hand.
It's something you'll never find
in another restaurant.
The only problem is, two.
I want 30.
I want them to come out
like chicken wings.
Stack 'em up!
Delicious.
Don't judge.
I've got your pork-belly nigiri.
-Oh, thank you.
-It's nice.
It's light.
It has a nice pop to it.
I've got curry fries.
I wasn't sure with the name
"Purgatory,"
what I was getting myself into.
It's definitely a bar
and a restaurant.
-Drinks are phenomenal.
-Drinks are amazing.
All right.
I dig it.
But also, you have
such unique dishes.
SERVER: Short-rib grilled cheese
for the bar.
MAN:
The short-rib grilled cheese
is pretty incredible.
Really, really tender rib meat.
Great flavor,
with that cheesy goodness.
-Short-rib grilled cheese?
-Yes, sir.
We start off with some
short ribs,
typically used
in Korean cooking.
Soy sauce.
Mirin.
It's been a common theme
around here.
Water.
Rice-wine vinegar.
A little garlic.
Garlic powder.
And some thyme.
How long is this
gonna simmer?
-Five to six hours.
-Really?
All right.
The crema.
We just start out with some
straight up sour cream.
Some lime juice.
Lemon juice.
Rice vinegar.
Let me guess, mirin?
Best friend, mirin.
That's our house crema.
All right.
Let's see it.
We start out with rustic
sourdough bread.
Pour that crema.
-Holy moly we're pouring crema.
-Yeah.
And then we're gonna take
the cheddar Monterey Jack mix,
some mozzarella.
-Okay.
-Put it right in the salamander.
-Melt up?
-Yep.
Bring it up to the flat-top.
There we go.
Put a little bit
of pickled reds in there.
[ Sproing! ]
Have I got a pickled onion.
And then, that short rib.
The 85-step grilled cheese,
comin' up!
Cut it diagonally.
Just like that.
And then we finish it off
with some chives.
♪♪
Wh-- cheese.
Chef, that's the most
interesting Asian short-rib
cheese-fondue dinner
wrapped in bread I've ever had.
[ Laughs ]
That is not
a grilled cheese, homes.
There's huge flavor
in the short rib.
The acid of the onions is
the much needed counter balance.
More cheese
than humanly consumable.
A good pull of cheese.
A good textural cheese.
The bread is
nice and crunchy.
Good bread-to-everything-else
ratio.
Calling that a grilled cheese
is like calling
a Ferrari just a car.
This is a supercar.
Excellent.
Thank you.
WOMAN:
I love a grilled cheese,
and this grilled cheese
stands out.
The short rib is full of flavor.
I've got some curry fries.
These guys do an awesome job
of taking your standard
bar food fare
and making it something
really memorable.
If they're gonna call
this bar food,
then the 24 Hour Le Mans
is a go-kart race.
That's delicious.
You rock.
Thank you.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry.
I'll looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
How about yourself? What's your
favorite thing on the menu?
The Curry Loco Moco.
Where was that all my day?
What's up with that, Chef?
There's some Curry Loco Moco
in the house?
I'm in Purgatory right now.
[ Laughter ]