Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Come on!
...we're stacking
and packing...
That's a monster.
...some showcase sandwiches...
The angels in Flavortown
are crying.
...like a killer Cuban
up in Washington state...
That sandwich tastes like
we're in South Beach, baby.
...an Austin joint rocking
new takes on old favorites...
That is, like,
a beacon of funk.
...plus a hip-hop
barbecue spot...
Just let your Soul-Glo.
These guys have too much fun
in this place.
...where the flavor got me
all fired up.
Freedom!
Where did that come from?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
I love coming
to Austin, Texas,
'cause I always
have a good time.
And after you have a night
of having a good time,
you wake up in the morning
or the late afternoon,
and you think, "I don't know.
Do I want breakfast, do I want
lunch, or do I want dinner?"
Hey, how about brunch offered
from 10:00 to 8:00?
You're going to love
this joint -- The Holy Roller.
♪♪
Casbah to 202.
This place is amazing.
Holy Roller is amazing.
Got your turkey melt
with fries.
MAN: I know I'm going to grab
something fun
that's just going
to knock me out with flavor.
FIERI: And that one-two punch
at this all-day brunch
is coming from owner
Callie Speer.
One of the things
that I like to do
is ask
"What did you eat growing up?"
and take those sort of
nostalgic moments
and turn them into something
a little more surprising.
I've got a meatloaf sandwich
with fries.
MAN: The meatloaf sandwich
reminds me of being a kid,
but just on a different level.
It's incredible,
it's massive.
And it has crunchy cheese on it,
so I love it.
Crunchy cheese.
When you say
"crunchy cheese,"
do you have to do
the shoulders?
You do.
Go like that.
BOTH: Crunchy cheese.
[ Laughs ]
Alright, what are we
making first?
This is like
our white toast.
We do all of our bread
in-house.
I dig it.
We're going to start with a roux
made with flour and milk.
AP flour, a little bit of
bread flour, active dry yeast,
salt, sugar, whole milk.
Couple eggs.
Eggs in there.
And then I'm going
to slowly add butter.
We form it.
Let this proof
for about 30 minutes,
and that will get egg-washed
and tossed in the oven
until golden brown.
Nice.
Next step.
Meatloaf. So, this recipe was
my grandmother's recipe,
which was terrible.
Okay.
So, let's take this thing
that everybody sort of hated
and turn it into
something enjoyable.
So we're going to take
this wheat bread.
Which you made.
Milk and eggs,
ground beef, salt.
Parsley, raw onion.
Parmesan.
See how we're working
as a team here?
And then fresh garlic.
And black pepper.
Alright.
And then we're going to be
putting that
in the same Pullman pan
that we do our toast in.
It gives us nice slices that
match the size of the bread.
Oh!
♪♪
That's a monster.
Five pounds.
I do curls with them
every morning.
You're so strong.
Yes, I know.
[ Laughs ]
So, we wrap it in plastic,
and then we're going
to wrap it in foil.
How long at what temp?
350.
45 minutes.
What are we into?
Crunchy cheese.
And she makes it look
so cool.
Do it like --
crunchy cheese.
Me, I start turning into
a whole earthquake.
We're going to sprinkle
Parmesan cheese into a nice,
even, thin layer
and bake it in the oven, 350,
till it gets golden brown.
It's like the most simple thing
in the entire world
and makes everything
taste better.
Doctor.
American pâté.
We're going to take a little bit
of clarified butter.
Wow, you really get
the butter on, don't you?
Mm-hmm.
And now,
down with the meatloaf.
Sear it on both sides with
a piece of mozzarella cheese.
Your horsey sauce.
Horseradish cream sauce.
Meatloaf on here.
Wow, it does fit perfect.
So cute, right?
Also made pickles.
And the best part of the whole
thing -- the crunchy cheese.
Doesn't get much better.
I mean, look at that thing.
Tour the showroom.
♪♪
The bread's dynamite.
It's soft, but it's got enough
texture that it stays together.
The juxtaposition of the crunchy
of the pickle and the...
Crunchy cheese.
...works dynamite.
What really ties it all together
is the horseradish cream sauce.
Fantastic.
That's a really heavy, rich
meatloaf with a lot of flavor.
It's not dry.
If you're going to make
a chef's meatloaf, that's it.
Meatloaf sandwich to 205.
One of the best sandwiches
I've had.
And the meatloaf
is delicious.
The bread is clearly baked
with love.
Pancakes with fried chicken
and sriracha butter.
How do you guys
describe this place?
Brunch meets punk rock meets
the best drinks in Austin.
It's very witty
and kitschy.
-Lights everywhere, and neon.
-It's really fun.
What are we going to do
after this?
What we call a Monte Bisco.
A Monte Bisco?
Which is -- ha-ha,
a Monte Cristo.
Just let me finish
what I'm having.
Alright,
so we're hanging out
at the Holy Roller
in Austin, Texas.
When we come back,
it's going to be time for the --
ha-ha, Monte Bisco.
Monte Bisco.
MAN: It's my go-to whenever
I need something
to probably
take a nap afterwards.
See you in a bit.
Monte Bisco.
I'm just following your lead.
It's your song.
I'm just singing back-up
right now.
Doop. Doop.
[ Both laugh ]
Welcome back.
"Triple D,"
hanging out in Austin, Texas,
at Holy Roller.
You got to love the name.
Pancakes, 205.
Imagine a bar that has
brunch all the time.
Like, your grandma's place
listening to rock music.
FIERI: And flipping grandma's
recipes on their head,
thanks to Chef Callie.
SPEER: Alright,
fire Monte Bisco.
The Monte Bisco brings
so many things
together that are
rally unexpected.
It's a warm, buttery,
soft biscuit.
Turkey, bologna, arugula.
Blackberry jam, powdered sugar.
But somehow, all these flavors
really work.
So the biscuit is going to be
the base of the dish
that we call the Monte Bisco,
which is our...
The Monte Bisco?
...play on a Monte Cristo.
But made with a biscuit?
But made with a biscuit.
Ha-ha.
I picked up on that.
Ah. See how clever we are.
Toss all this flour
into this food processor
with whole cubed butter.
Gravelly is the texture
we're looking for.
Technical term.
You give this a floof.
Buttermilk.
What is
this funking butter?
Heavy cream.
Sugar, salt.
Baking powder.
We're basically going
to laminate this dough.
The layers
we build of it.
Okay.
Correct.
And then at this point,
we shall roll them out.
Look at that.
Layer after layer after layer.
They'll get egg-washed
on the top.
In the oven.
What temp?
350, about 20 minutes.
Now we're into the turkey.
We brine our turkey
in a sweet tea brine.
Oh, I like sweet tea brine.
Peppercorns.
The lemons, we're going
to squeeze in here.
Coriander.
Brown sugar.
Honey.
Dip this tea bag in here.
Salt and some thyme, and then
hot water to steep it all.
And then we're going to cool it
down before we dump it
on top of turkey
and leave it overnight.
Then we just free-roast it.
350.
Where we at?
So, take this biscuit, and we're
going to do open-face like that.
Okay.
We're going to tatter up
some of this bologna
and this turkey
to get it a little bit brown.
That turkey's no joke.
So true.
Monte Bisco style.
Hit it
with the powdered sugar.
Blackberry thyme jam.
You make that?
We do.
Oh, the thyme in that
is money!
Turkey, bologna.
Nice small portion
you made there.
This is the best part
of the whole thing.
It's just kind of like aerated
Swiss cheese sauce.
You're making your own
Swiss cheese sauce?
Correct.
A little arugula salad,
and then a little lemon zest.
Normally, this gets an egg.
-Does it get a big egg on it?
-Right on top of it.
Not today...
I hate eggs.
...which makes me so sad.
There's a saying
on "Triple D,"
and that's "If it's funky,
I'll find it."
The tea brine of the turkey
is delicious.
The turkey's fantastic.
The biscuit itself --
just flaky, just perfect.
You tattered up the bologna,
throw it on the flat-top.
Then you made this aerated
Swiss cheese sauce,
you give me
a blackberry thyme jam,
powdered sugar,
baby arugula...
This sounds even weird for me
when you're saying it out loud.
...and lemon zest.
That is, like,
a beacon of funk.
Thank you.
Somebody made this up
at 4:00 in the morning.
[ Laughs ]
That's exactly
what happened.
But it's delicious.
Awesome.
Monte Bisco to 303.
It's a lot of different
flavor elements going on.
Sweet, savory, a little crisp
on all the meats.
Obviously the biscuit
is the best part.
Got your trash fries here.
The food is just fantastic
and over-the-top.
WOMAN: I mean, who doesn't love
brunch all day?
Sometimes you want brunch
at 5:00 at night
'cause you got up at 4:00.
Yes.
WOMAN: This feels like hangover
rock-and-roll food
that you just love.
FIERI: It's eclectic,
it's unique, it's different.
You're a rock star.
Watch out for this one.
FIERI: Up next, a '90s throwback
in Austin.
This is where things
are going to get weird.
Getting down
with the rib sandwich...
Throwing them bones.
...and putting out
brisket like a boss.
That's a bull right there,
buddy.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Austin, Texas,
to check out a barbecue joint.
You got it.
No, they don't
play country music.
No, they don't serve meat
by the pound.
They're not doing a meat
in three.
No, these dudes are all about
making some crazy,
whacked-out sandwiches,
playing some old-school hip-hop,
and they like to keep it
slow, low, and bangin'.
This is Slab.
♪♪
Alright,
you put that one down.
MAN: The thing about Slab --
it's irreverent because
of the '90s hip-hop vibe.
It's not traditional.
OG up.
El Jefe up.
But the care that they put into
smoking their meat,
it's really good.
FIERI: This backyard barbecue
party vibe
is hosted by renegade pit master
Mark Avalos
and his buddy,
Raf Robinson.
You know,
we're kids of hip-hop.
You're giving them
the great flavors of barbecue,
but putting it
in a new environment.
But how is the barbecue
different?
Barbecue sandwiches only.
No brisket plate?
No brisket plate.
No ribs?
Ribs, yes.
The McDowell --
a true rib sandwich.
And then we got
the Soul-Glo sauce --
No, it doesn't say
"Soul-Glo sauce."
Yes, sir.
I want the McDowell
with the Soul-Glo sauce.
SERVER: Got a McDowell
for table number seven.
It's perfect.
They take the bones out,
they put it between
two great pieces of bread
with a lot of other good stuff.
Nobody does anything
like this.
McDowell.
From the movie?
"Coming to America."
One of our favorite
Eddie Murphy movies.
Well, can't you see.
This is where things
are going to get weird.
First we're going to make
the rub.
Turbinado sugar, sea salt,
dry mustard, chili powder,
granulated garlic, cayenne,
black pepper, onion powder,
and cinnamon.
Dry-rub it up on
this St. Louis rib,
and how long's it going
to go down and smoke?
Three and a half,
four hours.
The pecan and the oak.
And now we're
into the Soul-Glo?
Just let your Soul-Glo.
These guys have too much fun
in this place,
I'm telling you right now.
We're making
the gold rush sauce.
The gold rush and the backyard
red become the Soul-Glo?
That is correct.
Dummy.
Mustard,
apple cider vinegar.
Sugar, water.
Brown sugar.
Chili powder.
You got it.
Black pepper.
I'm hungry.
Liquid smoke.
Yeah.
Soy?
Yes, sir.
White pepper.
Cayenne.
Holy heartburn, Batman.
Pepper flakes.
Add a little bit
of butter.
So cook this down,
and then mix that together
with the backyard red,
and that makes the Soul-Glo.
Soul-Glo.
Word.
Rack of ribs.
I dig it.
A little turn,
and a little slide.
Just like that.
Mm.
Look at that.
You can work here, brother.
Throwing them bones.
[ Laughs ]
Craps table in Flavortown,
baby.
And there you go.
I always start with
a little backyard.
And the mustard gold rush.
Just get a little bit more
sauce, some pickles and onions.
And that's all she wrote.
You guys are the first ones
in the history of "Triple D"
that I've seen actually
make a rib sandwich.
That's gangster.
♪♪
The angels in Flavortown
are crying.
[ Laughs ]
The rib meat --
super-tender.
The perfect bun.
The pickle and the onion
countering
the sweet of the sauce,
but there's something
about rib uniqueness
that you only get from the ribs.
You put it in a sandwich.
Well, bro, you don't only
pull it off, you crush it.
You just get freedom.
It's like William Wallace
made this.
[ Both laugh ]
Where did that come from?
Freedom!
Two McDowells here.
It's fantastic.
It's sweet, it's hot.
And the ribs are
super-tender.
I just love a good sandwich
like this.
The sides, the craft beers,
the ambiance of this kind
of place is why I come here.
How you homies doing over here,
man?
The music's always
taking you back.
And then you go to menu,
and then you see
all the relevant,
you know, hip-hop names.
Notorious P.I.G.,
Chicken.W.A.
It's good, man.
It's great.
MAN: But yet, they're serious
about the barbecue.
The brisket here
is so juicy and moist.
FIERI: But here, you're only
getting it on a sandwich.
We got a Jefe
and a potato salad.
MAN: Man, the El Jefe.
This is made out of brisket
and unicorn tears.
It's amazing.
El Jefe.
FIERI: Big, old
non-trimmed brisket.
Dalmatian rub right here.
Pepper, salt.
Dalmatian rub.
Smack it up, flip it,
and rub it down.
There you go.
That's it?
Then flip it to the other side,
brother.
We don't put that much
on the other side.
Okay.
Let that meat shine.
-Let the meat shine.
-We're going to let it sit.
24 hours, and then
go to the smoker.
10 to 12 hours, 250.
And what are we going
to smoke on?
Pecan and oak.
Brisket down.
Next up.
We got the backyard
red sauce.
Making some red sauce.
Where you at?
Backyard.
Oh, you making
backyard red sauce.
I'm on my way over.
[ Both laugh ]
Ketchup, apple cider vinegar,
"Worcestershire-shire."
Liquid smoke.
Whoa!
That is a lot
of liquid smoke.
-Mustard.
-A little molasses coming up.
Hot sauce, black pepper,
cumino,
granulated garlic,
onion powder,
and sea salt.
Let it come up to a boil,
and we're going to let it simmer
for about 20 minutes.
Bring the brisket out.
Look at that.
Chop it like it's hot.
Chop it like it's...
-Hot.
-[ Laughs ]
Nice bark on there.
Yes, sir.
Butter-toasted bun,
little backyard red.
Brisket's down.
Little bit more
of the backyard red.
And then we got some queso.
Why?
If you're in Texas, brother,
you eat some queso.
Peppers and onions.
Jalapeños.
Then we got another
Texas classic.
FIERI: Got to put a little
corn chip on it.
El Jefe.
Like a boss, brother.
Like a boss, huh?
Time to do some work.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
That's a bull right there,
buddy.
Wow.
When you make brisket
that's that honest
with just a touch of sauce,
that's enough.
That is fantastic.
The brisket is on-point, the
cheese sauce isn't overwhelming.
The backyard red
is the deal-changer, baby.
In the top of the best barbecue
sandwiches I've ever had.
Oh, my gosh.
I've got two El Jefes.
Smoked meat with
the hot jalapeño.
It's super-tasty.
You don't see a lot of queso
on sandwiches,
especially with barbecue,
but it balances everything out.
They know no boundaries,
do they?
No, they don't,
and that's why it's so cool.
You guys are doing it
your way.
You are legit
to your craft.
It's outrageous, man.
Thank you.
Well done.
Appreciate it, man.
♪♪
Coming up, in Pasco,
Washington...
Look at that.
...a sweet and savory spot...
That is a phenomenal
chicken sandwich.
...with the culinary chops...
He just makes it
look ridiculously easy.
...run five generations deep.
Oh, and look at him.
He gets all excited.
♪♪
So, Hunter's home
from college,
and we're up in Tri-Cities,
Washington.
Now, when the boys were younger,
they'd always ask,
"Can we go get doughnuts?"
And you know me.
I'm not really a sweets guy.
So, when I hear that there's
a father-son team
that are knocking out
scratch-made Mexican pastries
and bread, well, listen, that's
like two birds with one stone.
This is Vinny's Bakery.
Whoo!
♪♪
Nobody does it like
Vinny does it.
Pan con bistec.
Vinny is a magician
with food.
FIERI: "Vinny" is short for
Vinicio Marin Gomez,
whose kitchen magic
runs in his blood.
Fourth-generation baker.
They all used to bake
in Mexico.
And his son, Charlie,
is holding it down
as the fifth generation,
putting out pastries...
How many different items
do you guys bake?
-Ooh.
-20, 30-plus.
FIERI:
...and savory specialties.
WOMAN: Vinny makes his own
bread, not only for the bakery,
but he makes it
for his sandwiches.
My favorite is the Cuban.
Cuban sandwich,
table four!
I tried Cuban sandwiches
all over the country.
This is still the best
I've had.
Alright, guys.
We're going to make the baguette
for the sandwiches.
Okay.
We're going to start off
with water.
A little oil.
A little salt, the sugar.
Fresh yeast, and then...
High-gluten flour.
High-gluten.
Vinny, how long
is that going to run?
Five minutes.
Now we're going to roll it out
for the baguette?
Yep.
He just makes it look
ridiculously easy.
Well, his hands are magic.
And he can do it twice
as fast as anybody.
-That's how it works.
-Going to let them proof again.
CHARLIE: Score them on top and
put some butter on the score.
Bake them off at 400 degrees
for how long?
60 minutes.
What's the next step?
Pork for the Cuban.
We're going to make
the pork.
Oil, orange juice.
Cumin, black pepper.
Garlic.
Salt.
So, we're going to let
this braise
in this liquid
at what temp?
300 for eight hours.
What's the next step?
The hot sauce?
-Hot sauce for the sandwich.
Oh, and look at him.
He gets all excited.
So, we have some
boiled tomatillos.
Chili de arbol.
Paprika,
toasted sesame seeds.
First hot sauce I've ever seen
that has sesame seeds.
Salt.
Granulated garlic,
and some sweated onions.
♪♪
It's interesting.
A little toastiness to it.
Can I get it with a donut?
-No problem.
-A glass of milk.
Yeah. Pork.
Falls right apart.
Really good.
Mm.
It's the orange juice in there
that really makes it work.
Sear it off.
Some mayo, mustard, and pickles,
and some Swiss cheese.
Roasted pork.
Ham on top,
and then into the press.
Oh, Hunter, I thought he was
going to make you one.
That's alright.
You watch Daddy eat.
That's a sandwich
to be known for.
The bread is such
a key part of this.
Nice crust, but very thin
and very light on the inside.
And then you get to enjoy
all the delicious pork
and the ham and the mustard
and the pickle.
That was good.
And the hot sauce?
A spicy Cubano?
Spicy Cubano, yeah.
-Mm.
-And it's not too dry either.
A lot of times,
Cubans are dry.
Man, that is moist.
We're about as far
as far away from Miami --
from Cuba
that you could find,
and that sandwich tastes like
we're in South Beach, baby.
Delicious.
Two Cuban sandwiches,
coming up.
You get that soft, little crunch
and you get the cheese
and the meat that starts
melting in your mouth.
The pork is the most tender
I think I've ever had.
Vinny's sauce and that little
bit of sweat
right up on your forehead --
that's when it gets great.
I'm got mariachi fries,
Charlie.
Anybody that comes in here
one time always comes back.
FIERI: But at one point,
they didn't even think
they'd be able to stay open.
There's a story that I heard
about that
someone was shot
in front of the restaurant.
It had nothing to do
with you guys,
and that really affected
the business, right?
Yep.
MAN: He says, "I'm not doing
so great.
I think I'm going
to close my doors."
And I says, "No, you're not."
The Pasco Police Department
came and raised funds
to keep his doors open.
We put the word of mouth out
and we bought him
a couple more months,
and here we are
four years later.
FIERI: What's your favorite
thing on the menu?
The Vinny's
chicken sandwich.
-Legit.
Got Vinny's chicken sandwich.
MAN: Vinny knows his chicken.
Put it in that fresh bread,
and it's just perfect.
What are we going to
next?
Wait, Hunter, you're not
going to wait for your dad?
Oh, no.
See, you don't understand.
There's a new rooster
in the hen-house.
-Oh.
-Hey, hey, hey.
Alright, Vinny,
watch out for this kid.
This is what's going to happen.
You and I are asleep,
and you're coming to take
over the whole thing.
Give me a rundown, Chef.
What's next?
Okay.
A little marinade.
Oil.
Orange juice.
Salt, and the garlic.
-Paprika.
-Pepper.
And a little
of the cumino.
What's the next step?
Marinate the chicken.
CHARLIE: And it'll stay in there
for 12 hours.
Now, how are we going
to cook them?
On a flat-top.
Grilled zucchinis.
Grilled zucchini in
a chicken sandwich?
-Oh, yes.
-This I got to see.
Do you like zucchini?
I love zucchini.
Since when?
We're going to do the spicy mayo
for the sandwich.
Great.
For the Zucchini Twins.
Mayo down with some paprika.
Your dad loves paprika.
Sun-dried tomatoes,
and the kicker -- the chipotle.
So, the spicy mayo, the bread
that we baked ourselves,
and the zucchini,
and the chicken, fresh tomatoes,
red onion, in the panini.
This is the Vinny.
-This is the Vinny.
Okay.
♪♪
Are you not eating
at school?
What's going on?
Guys, that is a phenomenal
chicken sandwich.
The bread, of course,
is outstanding.
The flavors are in balance.
What do you think makes
the sandwich so dynamite?
HUNTER: The zucchini
and the tomatoes.
I like it.
We know you like it,
Hunter.
The zucchini melts.
It is so creamy.
That's a special
chicken sandwich.
SERVER: The Vinny's chicken
sandwich for you.
-Thank you.
-It's something very unique.
The zucchini.
Yeah, zucchini.
You can't beat it.
Mariachi fries!
Vinny's is the place to be.
MAN: There's nowhere that has
this combination of flavors
along with the warm
and welcoming feeling.
-You guys should be very proud.
-Thank you.
Congratulations.
I'll leave these two.
Okay.
Okay?
Come on, Vinny.
We'll take off.
We'll see you next week.
"Triple D."
Good luck, guys.
Clean it up.
So that's it for this trip.
But don't worry,
there's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Good afternoon, officer.
What seems to be the concern?
Well, Chef,
I know who you are.
Hunter,
I know who you are as well.
Christmas Rabbit,
I need to see some ID.
Where did he come from?
What the...?