You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how'd they doin'?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revs ]
FIERI: Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous,
dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
[ Engine revs ]
Like on this trip --
we're taking a bite out of Italy
in some surprising places...
-Buon appetito.
-Grazie.
FIERI:
...like Scottsdale, Arizona,
where authentic Italian
takes center stage...
If I cry during this,
please don't hold it against me.
...and wait till you meet
the star of the show.
[ Singing in Italian ]
A neighborhood joint
in San Antonio...
True commitment to doing it
the right way.
...serving certified pie
and made-from-scratch mozz.
Want to try this?
Seriously.
And in Austin, Texas,
a pizza place taking
the slice scene by storm...
It's a monster.
...a joint making its debut
right here on "Triple D Nation."
Look at that.
My mouth is watering
so bad.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
There are a million reasons
to come to Austin, Texas,
and when you get here,
you'll probably end up,
at some point in time,
on South Congress.
I mean, it is loaded with
restaurants and stores galore.
But if you don't want to
sit down and,
like,
have a full-blown meal
and you just want to get
yourself a killer slice quick,
this is your joint, Home Slice.
Wait a second.
"Take-out window service
next door"?
What?
FIERI:
Now, this play may never have
officially been on "Triple D,"
but I hit these guys up
every time I'm in Austin,
and, apparently,
it's been a while,
'cause I had no idea
they'd opened another place.
♪♪
MAN:
We walk right by here a lot.
This is great pizza,
and the food's excellent.
Chef Charles Corprew
keeps the pizza
coming while Jeff Mettler
keeps the joint running.
Home Slice was opened
in November of 2005.
METTLER:
It's an authentic New York-style
pizza restaurant here in Texas.
If this was in New York,
I'd eat it there, too.
FIERI:
So, give me the rundown,
'cause I walked up
to the takeout window,
and there's no more
takeout window.
Then it says comes this way
for more Home Slice.
What's the story?
That was the original takeout
window at our dine-in location.
So, over at the original,
that's the dine-in,
hangout, no takeout?
Yeah, full service.
-Full service?
When I remember
going there,
even waiting for a slice
took forever.
It's one of the reasons
why we opened this place,
so we could decrease
our pizza times at the dine-in.
Guy still slinging the pie,
the big monster?
-Uh-huh.
Every single dough
goes in the air.
So, our dough recipe
is really simple.
High-gluten flour, yeast, salt,
olive oil, and water
mixed for about 15 minutes
and then spends 3 days maturing
before it's ready
to stretch out.
This is the highlight.
This is what got me
addicted to it.
I mean, these guys
fly these pies.
Look at that.
See, it wouldn't be good
with the bling.
Look at the size of it.
All right, so now
what are we gonna make?
Margherita?
-Yes.
CORPREW: Start with some
olive oil as a base.
We'll hit it with
a little Pecorino Romano.
Little fresh garlic?
There's actually gonna be
a little provolone here.
Roma tomatoes.
Roma tomatoes here that
are diced, but not too much.
Don't want it to get soggy.
So the idea is to have
that nice,
crispy crust,
New York-style pizza
without being overloaded
with the toppings.
-Absolutely.
-Fresh mozz?
Fresh mozzarella here.
Now, this will go
in the deck oven.
550 degrees
for about 6 minutes.
We're gonna give it a spin and
then about another six minutes.
And when it's perfect,
it'll come out
kind of like a pretzel --
a little crispy on the outside,
soft and chewy on the inside.
-Nice.
-That's it.
Got to be careful
in how we slice it
to make sure that we have
exactly 1½ pieces
of the fresh mozz
on each slice.
-That's the rule, huh?
-Absolutely.
Finish it with the magic.
A little bit of fresh
basil chiffonade.
And that's all she wrote.
Beautiful and ready
for the taste test.
That really nice
thin crust,
just enough to hold
the pie together,
but it's got
a great chew.
Yep.
I like it.
It's air conditioned.
I'm gonna hang back here
more often.
This is where I'm gonna
come get my pizza.
Yeah, no problem.
We might put an apron on you
and put you to work.
Is that all right?
Yeah, I figured that
would be the next call.
WOMAN: The basil, the tomato,
the mozzarella --
it's a nice, even mix of it.
Gets a perfect level of tomato
in every bite,
and it just makes the pizza
come together really well.
So, here's where things
really get weird.
This is the six degrees
of "Triple D" separation.
You see, we got a good buddy
of ours named Improv, Mike,
that works
on "Guy's Grocery Games"
and on "Triple D,"
and he also happened to train
this guy at Home Slice.
You remember this cat?
-Hey, Mike.
Yeah,
what's going on, man?
-You used to work here?
-Yeah, man.
-And you trained him?
-Yeah.
You know that that means
you're gonna be throwing
some skins
at "Triple G."
I have no doubt.
FIERI:
But it's not all about the pie.
They've also got some classics
between the bread.
We're gonna do our 12-inch
Italian sub here.
So we're gonna start with
our fresh sesame-seed roll,
nice and
golden-brown toasted.
-Bake it fresh every morning.
-Yes, sir.
Get a good, little slathering
of mayonnaise on there.
I've never had
a sub from here.
I've only had slices of pie.
Okay, next up?
We're gonna put some fresh-
sliced provolone on there, ham.
I mean, this stuff is sliced
so wafer-thin
you can almost
see through it.
A little Genoa salami here,
a little hard salami,
follow it with
the capocollo.
Okay, let me just taste it just
in the name of science.
I understand.
And you guys are cutting these
cold cuts every morning?
Absolutely.
Every morning, fresh cut.
Makes all the difference,
the precut.
If you cut it too far
in advance,
it oxidizes,
changes the flavor a lot.
So cutting it fresh.
Okay, next up?
After that, we're gonna do some
shredded iceberg lettuce here.
We hit it with our sub sauce.
It's got crushed red pepper,
black pepper, chopped shallots
here, garlic, red-wine vinegar,
olive oil --
really brings out
the flavor of the meat.
Tomatoes on top.
Little thin-sliced onion.
That is what I'm talking about.
You're good to go.
That's a monster.
Cut it on a bias.
Plate that up.
You see how you can see
the different layers?
I mean, it looks like a picture,
like a painting.
My mouth is watering
so bad.
♪♪
So, the bed is money.
Cold cuts are fantastic
because they've been cut
and not stacked together,
so you can taste
all those different layers.
[ Talking with mouthful ]
And then that shredded lettuce
and the tomatoes and onions
adding the nice relief
of the acidity, bro.
Good stuff.
Nice job, chef.
Appreciate it.
Thanks.
Mmm.
The bread is fresh, and the meat
is just the right amount.
MAN:
The sub sauce is really good.
it complements the meat
quite well.
FIERI: [ Normal voice ]
You come to a city like this
and you drive by and go,
"Is that pizza joint
by the slice really that good?"
It is.
-We think so.
[ Laughs ]
I'm glad we can all agree.
Plus with a third location
in the north loop
also crushing it,
there's a lot more to like.
-Now, coming up in Arizona...
-Gnocchi alla Romana via.
-...off-the-hook Italian...
-That's fantastic.
-...straight from the real deal.
-The real one.
FIERI: Now, I've been to
plenty of Italian joints
serving up pasta and pizza,
but a market
in the middle of Arizona
cranking out
house-made prosciutto?
Well, I got to tell you,
it brings a tear to my eye.
Sempronio sandwich.
This is Andreoli Italian Grocer.
♪♪
This is the best place to eat
in Arizona by far, bar none.
FIERI:
And the man behind the magic?
That's Giovanni Scorzo.
Francesca, via.
"Leave the gun.
Grab the cannolis."
Okay.
Here cannoli.
That's the last cannoli
you're gonna eat.
No, I didn't want
the cannoli.
I wanted --
it's a saying.
-You say want a cannoli.
-No.
I've lost control
of this entire show.
So, when someone told me that
there was an Italian market
that made their own prosciutto,
I said, "I got to see this."
He said, "I'm amazed there's
somebody here in America
who makes
homemade prosciutto."
It's an Italian thing.
He was super happy.
If I cry during this,
please don't hold it against me.
Goes in sea salt from Sicily.
Okay, this is ready to --
[ Whistles ]
-How long?
-40 days.
It's gonna pull out
a bunch of the moisture.
-After 40 days...
-Right.
...we take it out,
we put it in fresh water, and we
make a marinade with Vino Rosso.
That good or more?
Hey, hey.
You can have too much
red wine?
Fresh garlic, black pepper,
then we grab this -- beautiful.
We just push down.
This is gonna go
in the refrigerator.
Like a month is enough.
Now we're gonna lock it down
with the fat and the flour.
Fresh ground pepper?
Yes. Smell.
I was gonna go to his nose
like this
full of the fat
from the pig.
No.
Listen, I might not speak
Italian,
but I am, buddy.
Go like this.
And that's to seal up
the bottom.
Tie the leg.
Put your finger there.
Your finger.
I know better than to put
my finger in there
when you're tying it.
Okay, this is gonna go
night-night for a year.
-Perfecto.
-Okay.
Now, this is the really
cool part.
To tell if they're done --
This is the femur of the horse?
-Mm-hmm.
-Perfect.
Good, huh?
-Okay.
-All right.
Make it a-nice.
Then we start from here.
There we go.
That's fantastic.
All right, let's make
the sandwich.
Prosciutto, mozzarella.
-Roasted peppers?
-Si, si.
And then we go like this,
and then a-boom, a-boom.
-Scusi.
-Si, si.
Buon appetito.
Grazie.
♪♪
Mmm. Great bread,
incredible meat.
You don't mess it up
with other things.
You get the experience
that Italians that slow down
at lunch time,
take the time to enjoy the food.
That's what this sandwich is,
what it's supposed to be.
Mmm.
FIERI:
But he's also got culinary
classics that don't take a year
to make,
like this scratch-made gnocchi.
My grandmother used to make
in Italy.
in real old fashion
with flour, potato.
I put a little nutmeg in mine.
And then we put one egg,
salt, nutmeg.
Now we have to mix it.
Very gentle.
I'm gonna roll it first,
then I'm gonna cut and roll
on the fork.
Put the gnocchi
in the boiling water.
That's tomato sauce.
Little cream.
Homemade pesto.
The sauce is ready.
Now we are waiting
for the gnocchi.
When they float,
means they are ready.
Perfect.
Now we sauté.
Little Parmigiano-Reggiano.
Gnocchi alla Corsara.
There are just these
little explosions of flavor.
It's a really rich dish,
but it's still really light.
You taste the tomato,
the basil, little pillows
of heaven in your mouth.
The "Triple D" episode
with Giovanni
and Guy
was typical Giovanni.
Does it snow in Arizona?
-Yeah.
-It does?
Yeah, one time.
"One time."
I was leaking all over.
"I was leaking."
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN:
His personality is bold,
just like his food.
Guy and I were having
a nice conversation...
Been to Italy?
Yes, many times.
...and Giovanni just
barreled in with his guitar.
[ Singing in Italian ]
I've just officially
lost the show.
-Coming up...
-Welcome to Giovanni's.
...I'm trying to reclaim
the reins...
I know.
Grazie.
...and get this train
back on track.
[ Italian accent ] Carrots?
No, I'm not
smelling the carrots.
I've been cruising about
five years down memory lane
to this Italian joint in the
middle of Scottsdale, Arizona...
You can cut the slice
for you.
Make sure, you know,
it's correct.
...and I have got my hands
full here.
In the top-10 crazies,
right here.
[ Laughter ]
All right, Chef,
what are we gonna make next?
We're gonna make the
bollito di carne, di manzo.
Bollito di carne.
First we start
with the peppercorns.
-Peppercorns.
-Our onions sticked with cloves.
Yeah. Cloves.
I know. Grazie.
Got to make me smell
everything in this.
SCORZO: For me,
when something is ready,
I can smell,
goes direct to my brain,
and I know it's perfect.
-Carrots?
No, I'm not smelling
the carrots.
Then we have celery,
Italian parsley, thyme.
[ Whistles ]
Bring this to boil,
then we add the meat.
How long's the meat
gonna go?
From 3 to 3½ hours.
Okay,
we go over the bollito.
We're gonna go to
the finish line, okay.
Finish line.
-Mmm.
-Easy.
Hey, hey.
[ Whistles ]
Wow.
Nice.
You can put the salsa verde.
So simple but so fulfilling.
It feeds not just your stomach,
feeds your soul.
It's the real deal, man.
FIERI:
And now this Italian stallion is
upping his cultural-comfort game
with this blast from the past.
Pappardelle with the
costine di maiale.
From my grandmother,
my aunt, my father --
people, they really like because
you can taste all the stew.
It makes people very happy.
Extra virgin olive oil,
little garlic,
chopped onions, put the ribs,
then the black pepper,
put some pinot grigio.
the bay leaves, and the tomato.
A little bit of water
in the sauce.
Now they can cook 1½ hour
to 2 hours.
And then we add the pappardelle
and black pepper,
and we toss it.
Pecorino cheese, black pepper
again, olive oil, and voilà.
The pappardelle,
they're cooked perfectly like
all of Giovanni's pasta.
It's al dente.
Pork short ribs are flavorful,
tender, just mouth-watering.
When you come down to
Arizona
and you enjoy
everything Scottsdale has,
if you don't come here,
you're out of your mind.
The real deal, man.
Out of bounds.
-The real one.
You're gonna come back.
Well, I guess he was right
about that.
You keep making that prosciutto,
and I'll keep coming back,
my brother.
You can count on it.
Now, coming up...
This you've never seen on
"Triple D."
...a San Antonio spot
firing up the perfect pie...
Mmm.
Dynamite.
...and they can prove it.
"Vera pizza napoletana."
That's what I was gonna say.
FIERI: You might not think
San Antonio, Texas,
would be home
to out-of-bounds Italian.
Well, let me just set
the record straight.
This place is making
their own mozz
and perfecting
the Neapolitan pie.
SERVER: Margherita.
FIERI: So for those who can't
make it to Italy,
there's
Dough Pizzeria Napoletana.
SERVER: Arugula prosciutto
and a Margherita.
This place was on "Triple D,"
and I am absolutely
not surprised.
It's an amazing experience.
It's Italian comfort food.
The flavors,
the feeling that you have
when you come into Dough,
it's amazing.
MAN: It reminds me of as
authentic Italian food
as I can possibly think of.
FIERI: That's 'cause owners
Doug and Lori Horn
are making pizza exactly the way
it's done in Naples,
and they can prove it.
Do they call it
"authentication" or...?
They call it
"vera pizza napoletana"...
That's what I was gonna say.
...which means "the real pizza."
Awesome.
This you've never seen
on "Triple D."
We follow the government
guidelines in Italy
to make authentic
pizza napoletana.
Look at that.
it's a fork mixer.
Super Megatron override
robotic dough-making machine.
Fantastic.
Gonna make our pizza
dough for the day.
Water, Sicilian sea salt.
-Everything's imported?
-Everything.
The yeast, specialty flour.
Look how gentle it is.
Fork mixers don't heat
the dough up.
Feel it sucking me in.
Oh, God, that was weird.
What's next, my brother?
We're making the mozzarella.
Add the blend of hot whole milk
and salted water.
Melt the curd.
Kind of push it around.
Let it start to absorb
some of this.
I can't resist.
The rings come off,
and it was just so cool
to watch him
take to it naturally.
Like pizza dough,
gonna roll it into itself?
Yeah, gonna roll it,
and then I just pinch it off.
That's it.
Into some ice water.
Let it just seize up
a little bit.
And now we'll cut it up
for the porco pizza.
Mmm.
I'm moving in.
Want to try this?
Seriously.
Ow, you bit me!
So the tomato sauce?
-It's San Marzano tomatoes.
Sicilian sea salt.
That's it.
Push it out to the edge.
Our sausage
all the way around.
Soppressata salami,
our house-made mozzarella,
thin-sliced cetta.
Finish it off
with smoked prosciutto.
Crazy.
That thing is rocking hot.
-Onto the plate.
-Take a look at that.
Mmm. Too bad you didn't
want any.
True commitment to doing it
the right way.
-Absolutely.
-Off the hook.
FIERI:
These days, he's doubling up
on that homemade mozz
with the burrata tre colore,
which is about as real-deal
Italian as you can get.
We added it to the menu
after Guy came.
This is a respect
for the Italian flag.
It's green, white, and red.
We just take ribbons
of mozzarella and make strands.
This is gonna be the basis
of the filling
for the tre colore burrata.
Add kitchen panna, it's heavy
cream, but it's reduced in half.
We've got the sun-dried
tomatoes marinated
with a little bit
of capers and garlic.
For the green,
we've got the pesto,
and we're just gonna
blend it right in.
As Guy would say...
[ Speaks with mouthful ]
It's Flavortown material.
Out of bounds.
This is beautifully melted
house-made mozzarella.
We're gonna take our filling
that we made,
and we're just gonna
put it right in the center.
Lace up the purse, so to speak,
tie with a green herb.
We're gonna put this
onto the plate.
Fresh heirloom tomatoes.
Beautiful prosciutto di Parma.
Extra-virgin olive oil
just to finish the dish.
Tre colore burrata.
That creamy center oozes out
when you slice into it,
and it's sensational.
The combination of homemade
mozzarella, sun-dried tomato,
the pesto,
and that prosciutto --
I'm telling you,
I did not want to share it.
FIERI:
I hear you, sister.
Prosciutto San Daniele
from Friuli.
FIERI:
This is expensive stuff.
It is.
It's deer.
It's actually pork,
but I agree with you.
It's delicious.
He's, like, such a pig fan,
so I'm cutting more prosciutto,
and he's dropping in his mouth.
You only should eat
the prosciutto thinly sliced.
Oh.
Try this again.
Dynamite.
I'm eating it
in cooked chunks.
We did the prosciutto pizza.
These are the melted leeks,
cream, wine, grated fontina,
not too much, pulled prosciutto,
caramelized onions,
rosemary-marinated olives,
fresh rosemary.
Wow.
Huge flavor.
And out we go.
Mmm. Mmm.
Awesome, awesome, awesome.
SERVER: I got a bunch
of tickets on hold.
One "Triple D" aired, it was
chaotic, nutty, wonderful.
Nice job, team.
We opened up in Plano, Texas,
downtown San Antonio.
Even though they've grown
so much,
they're keeping the quality,
they're expanding
their menu now,
and the desserts
are out of this world.
FIERI: Like the brand-new
limoncello torta.
Well, we make our own
limoncello,
and we had so much of it
we said,
"Hey, we should make some
kind of dessert with it."
Now it's a big hit.
It's a multilayer cake.
We're gonna start off
soaking ladyfingers
in a little limoncello,
and we're just gonna line
the bottom of the pan.
This is the first layer.
This is the ricotta filling.
Gonna repeat.
Ladyfingers.
This is the second layer,
this is the lemon curd,
and this is where
the tang comes in.
This is the last layer --
nice, creamy whipped cream.
Candied lemon zest right on top.
Limoncello torta.
The fresh lemon flavor of it
and the candied lemon zest
that he puts on top
balances it out
really well with
a little bit of acidity.
It's beautiful.
FIERI:
Doug is your name.
Your last name is...
Horn.
The "Doug H."
is kind of the trifecta
because it's Doug Horn,
dough on your pizza,
and make some dough.
You've pulled all three.
Now, that's an equation
I can get on board with.
Whether it's dividing up pie
in a by-the-slice
spot in Austin,
adding even more authentic
Italian to the menu in Arizona,
or a neighborhood pizzeria
in San Antonio
multiplying for the masses,
and we'll keep meeting new faces
and hitting up
familiar places next time
on "Triple D Nation."
-Are you helping?
-I'm helping.
-I don't think so.
-What?
What do you --
-Look, it's all wet.
Who left the water in there?
I didn't leave it in there.
-Yeah, you did.
-No, I didn't do it.
[ Laughs ]