You know, people are
asking me all the time,
Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out in that one city
when you were doing "Triple D,"
how'd they do it?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revving ]
Over the years, I've
seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning!
'Cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowin' up,
and we're goin' back
to see what's cookin'.
Like on this trip.
My mouth seriously
just started to water.
In Georgia...
[ Plate shatters ]
-Hey!
-Opa!
Welcome, Guy Fieri is here!
...a "Triple D" OG...
I'm driving the bus
to the Flavortown.
...findin' new ways
to fill me up.
Nice seeing you guys.
No, I'm leaving!
-Done.
-One more!
An urban farm in Arizona...
That's excellent, man.
Still bringing the bounty
from the backyard.
That's a mack daddy patty.
Plus a head-scratching
San Antonio spot...
-There's a carwash.
-Right.
-Laundromat.
...complete with
Texas-sized tastes.
The only thing that
I don't like about this
is that it's all gone.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
[ Car door closes ]
So I'm here in Atlanta, Georgia,
shooting "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives,"
and you know what that means
is I gotta come back
and check out some
"Triple D" OG joints.
So I hear that uncle Gus
has taken off
and gone to the big city,
but the menu is still the same,
serving up those traditional
diner classics,
and they may have added
a little bit of neon.
This is the Marietta Diner.
♪♪
Spanakopita are ready,
both ready, pick up guys.
Marietta Diner is a landmark.
It's become a destination.
People travel from outside
of town to come here.
I got to see it on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I came here to try it out,
and it's been wonderful.
If Guy was there,
it's gonna be great.
There is the real deal.
What's up brother?
How are you, man?
I can see the energy bill
from 50 miles down the way.
Can't miss it, ah?
Gus Tselios grew up
in a big diner family
near New York City.
Do you like
your breakfast?
With mom, dad, cousins,
even head chef, Uncle Gus.
I'm Uncle Gus.
I'm driving the bus
to the Flavortown.
I got to get an Uncle Gus.
-Where's uncle Gus?
-Uncle Gus is in New York.
Uncle Gus drive the bus.
I would always make the
little joke about Flavortown,
but it wasn't until we had
Uncle Gus drive the bus.
We should almost have
a plaque in the ground
that is one of the founding
restaurants of Flavortown.
[ Horn honks ]
FIERI: And, boy, did Uncle Gus
leave an impression.
What're we gonna make now?
Pastitsio, a Greek
version of a lasagna.
Olive oil, onion,
I'll do my garlic.
He's like a speed chef.
Cinnamon stick,
and now I put my ground beef.
I am glad that none of
my personal belongings
were sitting
on that counter,
'cause it's speed cookin'
with Uncle Gus.
[Gus laughs]
Okay, Uncle Gus gone wild,
are we gonna put it in the oven?
-Yes.
-Look at that.
[ Guy whistles ]
Mmm.
Wow, that's good.
You know what flavor
I get right off the bat?
The nutmeg.
How did you know
I was gonna say nutmeg?
I think I know
what you're eating.
Uncle Gus may have moved away,
but Gus 2.0 is still
surrounded by family.
My dad.
Hey boss, how are --
[ Plate shatters ]
-Hey!
-Opa!
Welcome!
Guy Fieri's here!
Opa!
Did you see that? Please
tell me you got that.
We don't have Uncle Gus,
but we got Papa George.
That was well done.
Opa!
FIERI:
Papa George is the inspiration
behind one of Gus's new hits.
Steak tips Papa George
is after my dad.
My dad used to go around to
the few tables that we had
and he would give them a
sample with his Greek accent.
"Try this, this is
a present from me."
People would go mad for this,
so we put it on the menu.
You char grill
the skirt steak.
We use outside skirt,
season it with a
little salt and pepper.
Start sauteing some
mushrooms, onions,
put a little sliced
garlic in there.
Salt and pepper,
granulated garlic.
Take our steak, slice
it fajita style.
Brown gravy,
add a little au jus,
Marsala wine.
Steak sauce,
Worcestershire sauce,
add the skirt steak,
fresh lemon,
little rice pilaf,
steak tips
and a little piece
of feta cheese
with some char
grilled pita bread.
Mmm. Dude, is that
the Marsala in there --
Worcestershire and Marsala
and steak sauce?
Yes, combo.
I want a steak sandwich
of that.
A toasted hoagie.
Seriously, it's not good,
it's phenomenal.
Pick up please.
Steak tips themselves
are so tender
and it is a beautiful
cut of meat.
It's really good.
I love the flavors and
I really like the sauce.
There's something in there.
It's a new flavor.
It's a new spice.
It's a winner.
Mmm.
What're these here?
GUS: Beef stroganoff.
When I think of an
old school diner dish
it would be something
like beef stroganoff.
It's been on the menu since
the day we opened,
about 25 years now.
We used to have it only
once a week, every Friday,
but it became so popular
we have it on the
menu everyday now.
Onions, chopped garlic.
We use beef brisket,
and we cut it into cubes.
We find it very tender.
Little bit of salt,
black pepper,
white pepper,
granulated garlic,
bay leafs, chicken base,
water.
Cover it. Let it cook.
Add the mushrooms and
mix 'em up with the meat.
The main ingredient of the
stroganoff is a sour cream.
We're gonna add
a little heavy cream,
a little corn starch,
a little bit of white wine.
We serve the beef stroganoff
with egg noodles,
a little Parmesan cheese,
and a little parsley.
The meat's super tender.
It's not heavy.
Actually, the sauce
is kind of light.
It's got real beef flavor.
This dish has been so popular,
people will call,
they'll say "please reserve me
two stroganoffs.
I'll wait for the table,
but don't run out
of beef stroganoff."
Outstanding.
WOMAN: The noodles, the sauce,
the beef, everything just
beautifully blended,
it tastes delicious.
Beef stroganoff is always
one of my go-to menu items.
Hits all the taste buds in
my mouth.
It's unbelievable.
Delicious.
FIERI: Of course
they're still serving up
the same Greek staples that
I had in my first go around.
You get a free little
piece of spanakopita.
It's like a Greek touch.
Okay, so how do we make it?
Melt our butter,
extra virgin olive oil.
Now we take our onions,
fresh scallions, fresh dill,
black pepper, little nutmeg.
-Really?
-Little salt,
got our spinach over here.
Want me to get all
the stuff outta here?
Yeah yeah yeah,
that's the flavor.
Gonna add our feta cheese.
Now we put our eggs.
That's the binder.
Yep.
And now we're going to layer
800,000 sheets
of phyllo dough.
Perfect.
Crooked lines are okay?
You gotta gimme
some room here.
You know what the
secret ingredient is?
Smell it.
Be careful.
Water?
[ Laughs ]
It's water, H2O.
Put a little bit of
water on top of the phyllo,
it doesn't break apart.
Bless this spinach pie.
[ Laughs ]
I pray that this spinach pie
is the best one I've ever made.
Oh, man. That is excellent.
Man, that's great flavor.
That's awesome.
Thank you.
FIERI: But he's not just pulling
from his own cultural cookbook.
That's a good-looking
paella.
When we come back,
Gus is driving the bus
on an international expedition.
Little bit like a jambalaya.
It's fantastic.
Grab a fork.
Now we're gonna eat this.
[ Laughs ]
Order up.
FIERI:
I'm reliving the good ol' days
outside Atlanta
in Marietta, Georgia.
Well here's a classic one for
ya -- a big, shiny, steel diner.
Run by a big extended family
with a huge menu
full of all kinds of food,
especially Greek.
It's been 10 years,
and I gotta say,
things look a little different.
Wow.
This whole...
Yeah, what changed,
besides everything?
This was the lobby.
This was the lobby
of the diner.
This was it, pre "Triple D."
So I helped pave some
of this boulevard.
"Triple D" shows up, and you
gotta make the lobby bigger.
And the menu is also amped up
with over 500 choices
from all over the world.
When Guy was here the first
time, he had the seafood paella.
How many people's this feed?
Nobody leaves hungry
in this place.
Starting with the chicken,
salmon, put a lobster tail.
Look at those.
Use a scallop,
a spoon of garlic,
a little Cajun seasoning.
That's a good-looking
paella.
For a party of 10.
Fresh basil, ice,
chopped clams here,
drop add a little
marinara sauce.
This is one unique
paella, man.
I don't know if
I want to eat it
or have my picture
taken with it.
Great flavor,
individual flavor.
You know what I'd like
to enjoy right after
eating something
like this?
Tell me.
A nap.
But there's no time to snooze
with the way Gus 2.0
runs his kitchen.
Seafood Mardi Gras.
This is gorgeous.
If you like it, I'm gonna call
it Guy's Seafood Mardi Gras.
Lobster tail, chicken tenders,
and our sea scallops.
Our shrimp, Italian sausage.
They're gonna join the party.
Add some onions, add some salt,
some white pepper,
granulated garlic,
basil, Old Bay.
Gonna add
some chopped clams,
mussels, Alfredo sauce,
Cajun seasoning.
That's gonna be our base,
pour everything right on
top of the penne pasta.
Lobster tail, put 'em
it right on top.
There's our seafood
Mardi Gras.
It's fantastic.
If you call it Mardi Gras,
you think Cajun,
you think too much spice,
it's gonna blow it out.
I don't like
too much spice
cause then you don't
taste the food.
Exactly.
A little bit like a jambalaya.
It's a paella on top
of penne Mardi Gras,
but in a Cajun
Alfredo sauce.
Of course it is.
Great dish, I like it.
Seafood Mardi Gras is
a festival of flavors.
The Alfredo sauce is fabulous.
It's not too thick.
There's all kinds of
seasonings, lemon.
It's just an explosion
in the mouth.
You've got mussels, lobster,
clams, scallops, shrimp.
It is so tasty.
♪♪
-10 years ago, we were here?
-About 10 years ago, yeah.
The funny part is
when people come here
they wanna know,
"What did Guy eat?"
I tell them everything.
Am I lying?
That's exactly why
he's doing this to me.
I gotta leave, dude.
Got to taste this, one more.
No. Okay, I'm out of here.
Nice seeing you, Gus.
Hey, Guy, Guy...
Take care.
Which way is the back door?
Come on. Just one more.
Wait, come back!
No, I'm leaving, Gus!
One more! [ Laughs ]
♪♪
I mean come on, Gus,
how much food do you
think a guy can eat?
Remember,
I still have to actually
try to fit in the Camaro.
Plus, there's more to
fill up on in Arizona.
Doctor it up,
doctor.
At joint that's turning
the tables
on farm-fresh fast food.
That's out of bounds
ahi, man,
also known as terrific tuna.
♪♪
Back in 2008,
I found a place
in Gilbert, Arizona,
that gives new meaning
to the term "fast food"
since they go grocery shopping
right outside their backdoor.
You think you know
farm to table?
Well, at this place the table
is actually on the farm.
This is Joe's Farm Grill.
♪♪
And a gouda garlic
bacon burger.
MAN: Oh, my goodness.
That looks good.
It's definitely not
your average burger bar.
This is the place you go to
if you want a good,
straight from the farm
to the table type meal.
They grow all of
their own vegetables.
Everything is farm fresh.
FIERI: That farm belongs
to Joe Johnston,
who grew up here and
turned his old family home
into a restaurant.
This was originally
your house?
It was.
That was originally
your farm?
We do have
our own local farm
when using organic produce.
FIERI: And Joe's chefs use
those homegrown goods
on just about everything.
-Burgers are big?
-Huge.
When Guy came, he had
the fontina burger.
We use 1/3 pound
all Arizona beef.
FIERI: Raised, butchered,
everything for you guys?
Oh, yeah.
Sauteed mushrooms.
Normal condiment bar you
find in all fast food joints.
We use as much as we
can from the farm.
We make this here with
the basil that we --
That you grow, I know.
Roasted peppers.
That we also grow.
Right.
And then arugula.
Look at that.
That's a mack daddy patty.
Nice, tender, big mushroom
flavor, the arugula,
that's excellent, man.
When Guy came to the restaurant,
it was a brand new restaurant,
14 months old.
We were selling 1,400 burgers
a week.
Now we've doubled that.
We're selling
so many more things
to so many more customers.
FIERI:
And they're getting creative,
like with their new top seller,
the gouda garlic bacon
burger stack.
We ran of a series of
specials to find out
what people really liked,
and this one hit it
out of the ballpark.
So, we start with
the Caesar dressing,
the red wine vinegar,
add some lemon juice,
some anchovy paste,
the Dijon mustard,
Worcestershire sauce,
and then fresh minced garlic,
blended olive oil,
grated Pecorino Romano cheese,
mayonnaise,
and fresh chopped oregano.
Then we season our ground beef
patty with roasted garlic.
Then we enrobe
the applewood smoked bacon
with gouda,
and then we add
the Caesar dressing,
we have a red onion slice
caramelized,
tomato, pickles,
and then we add some
of our barbecue sauce.
It's such a messy burger.
It's just not right to give it
to a customer without gloves.
Alright guys, I got
a gouda burger. Let's go.
It's the juiciest burger
I've ever had.
It's a mouthful.
Just a plethora of flavors
and tastes whenever
you bite into it.
FIERI: And if you need
a bigger garlic fix...
For the garlic fries, we get
garlic, and we mince it up.
Olive oil, parsley,
four pepper corn blend
with Pecorino Romano,
and then that tops our fries.
There are crispy and salty,
and then when you dip
them into the Caesar sauce,
it just made it perfect.
JOE:
We have this breading machine,
and Guy was totally
fascinated by it.
Watch it come out
the other end.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
That's awesome!
That's awesome, dude.
He thought it was just amazing.
Almost as amazing as
the ahi tuna burger.
Primarily with this, I like to
go to the hottest part
of the grill.
This is fast food at its finest.
Doctor it up, doctor.
We gotta get the
Asian slaw going.
Goes with the Asian salad
that goes on the tuna?
Correct.
Start with the chili paste,
and then the lime to break
that down a little bit.
Sesame seed, chopped mint,
and then chopped basil.
Again what exactly
you'd expect to find
at a fast-food
restaurant.
Yeah.
Let's pull it.
That's nice and rare.
Yes.
My mouth just seriously
started to water.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
That's out of bounds ahi, man,
also known as terrific tuna.
He was blown away that that was
at a fast-food restaurant.
Our sales shot up in that,
so now it's one of
our better sellers.
And you're getting what you
thought you were gonna get.
You thought it was gonna
turn out like this.
Yes, and we hope it'll
get bigger still.
Yep, it sure did.
Last time Guy was here, this
was the end of the restaurant.
Now we've expanded out
and almost doubled
our seating capacity.
FIERI: And they're also gearing
up for breakfast all day
with this twist on an old
classic, waffles and ribs.
JOE: We start out with
baby back ribs,
our special rib rub --
brown sugar, cane sugar.
We've got granulated garlic,
black pepper, cayenne pepper,
to make it spicy,
and then we smoke them
for four and a half hours,
take 'em out,
and then we liberally apply
our barbecue sauce.
And then we put 'em
in for two more hours
to meld the flavors together.
We splay out the two waffles,
the beautiful ribs,
and then we add
a little sprinkle
of garnish on it, as well.
Waffle and ribs.
[ Bell dings ]
You got a perfect waffle,
not breaded chicken --
real fall-off-the-bone ribs.
It's like heaven.
So a man that's having great
success, rocking the numbers,
people are thrilled.
Watch out, this guy
for president.
[ "Yankee Doodle" plays ]
[ Birds chirping ]
How do we even find
these crazy places?
At the next stop, San Antonio...
Ooh, yeah.
...to another
not-on-the-radar restaurant...
It's a little funky.
Well, no, if it's funky,
it's fun, we'll find it.
That's why we're here.
...where your table's got
a totally different view.
Wow, at a carwash?
♪♪
I like to think I've seen
just about everything
on my marathon road trip
across the country.
But this joint I found
in San Antonio,
well, it had me super confused.
A laundromat, a carwash,
and a funky little dive
serving up killer creations.
Yes, this is The Cove.
♪♪
WOMAN: It's a real hot spot
in the community.
I mean where else do
you have a laundromat,
car wash, and great burgers
and fish tacos
all in one spot?
When "Triple D" was here,
we were here.
So we watched it grow up
from just a little tiny place
into this beautiful structure
that we have here today.
FIERI: And it's all because
owner Lisa Avestas
thought outside the box.
There's a carwash.
Right.
Laundromat.
And in the middle,
where it's supposed to be,
like, the snack bar,
is a full-blown restaurant.
The Cove was born in 2001,
and it was really
an afterthought,
it's kind of hidden,
like a cove.
You can see the car wash
and the laundromat,
but until you come back here,
you don't really know
what's in The Cove.
It's a little funky.
Well, no, if it's funky,
it's fun, we'll find it.
I mean,
that's why we're here.
We're gonna make a marinade
for our portobello
and spinach quesadilla.
Balsamic vinegar,
extra virgin olive oil --
gotta have that -- salt,
herbs de Provence.
Wait wait wait wait, that
might be one of the first times
I've ever seen herbs de Provence
brought into the play.
Look at that.
That's like a savory syrup.
Throw 'em on the grill,
about 20 minutes.
So while those are going,
what else do we do?
The poblano sauce.
Poblanos and serranos?
Serranos right.
-Yogurt.
-Don't push my head in there.
Good for you.
Mayonnaise, not so good
for you, but tastes good.
And sour cream.
Salt,
fresh ground pepper.
Did you grind that pepper?
Yes we did.
We grind all our pepper.
Ohh!
♪♪
Little bit of heat,
nice big --
Wah, that's a lot of heat.
-Whew.
-Yeah.
Take our portobello
mushroom, slice it up.
On the flat top.
Now we wanna add our red onion,
organic spinach.
Cover those
for just a second.
Gonna wilt that spinach
a little bit.
-Okay. Cheese.
-Cheese.
Cheese,
need the cheese.
FIERI: Look at the size
of this thing.
Fold it over.
He was kind of like,
this is really healthy.
That's good. Wow!
I already feel healthier.
You look healthy.
[ Laughs ]
I would have the cleanest
car in San Antonio
if I knew this was here.
I'd be here everyday
washing it.
FIERI: Now she's churning out
new meatless options
like a jackfruit sandwich
called, of course,
the captain jack.
LISA: We use jackfruit.
It's texture is very
similar to pulled pork.
We add ground cumin,
garlic salt, and pepper.
After that we add our
blackberry barbecue sauce.
we're gonna put a four ounce
portion on the hot griddle.
We add a little more of our
blackberry barbecue sauce
and some vegan mayo.
Slice onions, pickles,
coleslaw, and it's ready to go.
Two captain jacks.
It's sweet, it's spicy,
surprisingly meaty tasting.
WOMAN:
It's kinda like a pulled pork.
I eat meat all day,
but that was excellent.
FIERI: But she does cater
to the meat eaters, too.
Like with the lamb burger.
Wow! Some of the best lamb
burger I've every had.
At a car wash?
And a brand new
Chilango burger.
I found this amazing
taco place in Mexico City
and love this sauce.
We start with piloncillo, which
is an unrefined sugar.
Then we add a little
tamarindo juice,
and we cook it down.
Add roasted tomatoes,
roasted onions,
whole garlic, and cilantro.
Let that cook down, and then
we add chipotle peppers.
We're gonna use a grass fed
beef patty, Oaxacan cheese,
put that on a toasted bun.
We top that with tamarindo
sauce.
Avocado, slice
tomato, red onions.
♪♪
I have a Chilango burger.
WOMAN: The cheese melts over
the patty,
just really beautiful,
and then the sauce is just that
little bit of a sweetness to it.
-Wasn't that crazy?!
-Ah-choo!
LISA: We doubled the
size of the kitchen,
and we added a dog park.
Can you hear the dogs?
[ Dogs barking ]
There they are.
When you have a passion
for something
and you work hard at it,
it kinda works out.
The only thing that
I don't like about this
is that...it's all gone.
I'll make you
another one.
All right.
Lisa also opened a second place,
and get this --
it's a restaurant
combined with a yoga studio,
because why not, right?
Yoga studio, carwash.
I mean you never know
what you're gonna find
when you take a spin
around Flavortown.
-What's up?
-Opa!
Like Gus in Georgia,
who pushes his 24-hour diner
into the red zone,
over to Arizona where Joe
keeps the food funky fresh
at his farm and table joint.
And deep at the heart of Texas,
there's Lisa killing it
with her creative combos
in and out of the kitchen.
And they're not the only ones.
We got plenty more places
to pop into next time
on "Triple D Nation."
Sing the ingredients.
♪ We got-ah the meat ♪
♪ Cubes meat over here,
we put some water ♪
[ Uncle Gus and Guy laughing ]