You know, people are askin' me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doin'
'Triple D' -- how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning,
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowin' up,
and we're goin' back
to see what's cookin'.
Like on this trip --
an off-the-Strip spot
in Vegas
known for Bulgarian bites...
-That is killer.
-Uh...
...and pullin' off the ultimate
"Triple D" prank.
-No way!
-Yes!
[ Laughing ]
Plus, in Atlanta...
We're mining for ore today!
[ Laughs ]
...a punk-rock bar
servin' up anything
but the basics.
It's like makin' a U-turn
in Flavortown.
And in Taylor, Texas...
-Yay, boy!
...an out-of-bounds
barbecue legend is remembered.
Oh, gosh, it's so crazy.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So I just got done shooting
"Triple D" in Austin, Texas,
and I knew that I was only
about 30 minutes
away from
the great town of Taylor.
You see, this is where we shot
one of our first
"Triple D" barbecue joints.
Oh, I mean, this place
in legendary.
They've won every award,
they're recognized
by the barbecue community,
and I've always wanted
to come back.
This is Louie Mueller's.
-MAN: Thank you.
-Lunch.
Louie Mueller's just a staple
for the state of Texas.
It's absolutely old-school
barbecue.
Barbecue has become trendy,
particularly in Austin,
but all roads lead back
to Louie Mueller.
Yeah, I made the best choice
coming to Louie Mueller's
'cause he makes
the best barbecue.
Like stepping back in time.
♪♪
This is how I remember it
when we came here 12 years ago.
Wow!
That's when I met barbecue
legend Bobby Mueller.
Walk me through the process
of cooking a brisket.
You got your fires goin',
you got your meat laid out here,
put your rub on it,
which is no more
than salt and pepper.
Feel like I'm in massage
school or something.
Okay.
And anyone helping out
stuck to the rules.
Just like Bobby's
been doing it for years.
Do you want me to get it
down in the cracks?
I want -- yay, boy!
Into the pit.
-There you go, you got it.
-[ Coughs ]
Ah.
And that's it.
And you think the key
to this is the oak?
I think that's what gives it
the flavor.
-Wow!
-The whole deal here.
And that one's ready
to come off.
♪♪
Oh! That's pretty outstanding,
gentleman.
I love the brisket.
You get the good bark,
then it's moist
and delicious on the inside.
It melts in your mouth.
You hardly have to have
a knife to cut it.
FIERI:
But he wasn't the O.G. here.
His dad, Louie Mueller,
started this place seven years
before Bobby
took the reins in 1974.
And now that Bobby's
passed away, his son Wayne
is keeping things
on track.
-How ya doin', brother?
-Good to see you.
How long since
your dad passed?
He passed about a year
and a half after you were here,
so it's been
10 years already.
Great guy. Definitely one of
the mayors of Flavortown.
[ Laughs ]
Great, great.
FIERI: And the slogan
at this joint has always been
"Give the people
what they want."
What can we get ya, buddy?
What do you serve on a portion?
Whatever they order.
We don't have a set plate
for anybody.
They come up the counter
and just call it,
two or three slices.
-Sir?
-Two slices of brisket.
MAN: You wanna wait in line
at 10:30
and get here
as quick as possible
because it's gonna be gone.
"Until sold out."
What?
But fortunately for me,
I beat the crowds.
What is this monstrosity?
That monstrosity
is our beef rib --
the most acclaimed cut
of barbecue.
This is what people travel
around the world to come eat.
We use a simple
salt-pepper recipe --
nine-to-one pepper
to salt ratio.
Small amount of water.
We apply it liberally.
We believe black pepper to be
a fifth food group around here.
It seems excessive.
I promise you it's not.
This guy will be cooking for the
next five to six hours, 325.
♪♪
That's not a beef rib.
That's like a whole half a cow.
It's for sharing.
It's outrageous.
It's just salt and pepper.
That's another thing.
You know, getting back
to that gospel
of doing it
the right way.
-Yeah.
-Mmm!
That beef rib is
fall-off-the-bone.
It's a caveman portion.
It's incredible.
Fat's rendered just right.
Every bite is flavorful,
good Texas beef rib.
♪♪
And where's your wood
come from?
Trees.
Oh, is that how this is
gonna go today?
[ Laughs ] No.
N-No, I like it.
Where you guys getting
all the meat?
From cows.
[ Laughs ]
That apple don't fall too far
from the tree, now does it?
This is a beef dip
that we've been using
for quite a long time.
This is what I was
looking for.
This is my grandfather's
recipe.
People assume that
it's a barbecue sauce,
but it's not a sauce at all.
It's more like a jus dip.
First step is add
our base of onions.
Add our tomato flavoring.
Half a pound of margarine.
Salt, pepper.
Beef bouillon cubes.
Lastly, a few gallons of water.
On to the stove and to a boil.
Simmer about an hour,
hour and a half,
just until the onions
are fully stewed.
Then it's ready to serve.
It is delicious.
Sorry that I'm just gonna sit
here and chow this down
while I talk to him.
It doesn't mask the taste
of the barbecue.
It just adds a little bit
of extra seasoning
and flavor and moistness to it,
and it's very unique.
Kinda along the sweet
and sour side.
It was so delicious.
♪♪
It's funny because as much as
I thought I knew about food
when I started "Triple D,"
coming here with your dad
that morning,
I mean, it was just surreal.
-Getting in the way.
-[ Laughs ]
It's real smokey in here now.
-This is clear.
-Oh.
We've done hundreds and hundreds
of barbecue joints by now,
and they'll say,
"Where's your favorites?"
I said, "Man, it's where
I cut my teeth.
It's over at Louie Mueller's."
And I'm not the only one
who thought so.
Coming up...
Y'all got
a James Beard Award?
Scratch-made sausage...
What are we gonna do, look for
a needle in a haystack?
...boundless barbecue...
That's delicious.
and the "Triple-D Nation"
took notice.
Like, I've been there.
♪♪
FIERI: Back in the beginning
of "Triple D,"
I went to this barbecue joint
that had been on my radar.
One of the best things
about doing
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
is I get to visit some places
I'm a real fan of.
So when I get a chance to try
some famous brisket
at Louie Mueller's
in Taylor, Texas,
well, today's
gonna be a good day.
Without question,
you guys shaped the show.
Pops did.
That's so cool
for you to say, man.
-Oh, it's the truth, man.
-Thank you.
-It's the straight-up truth.
-Very honored.
FIERI:
Now, when I first rolled up,
it was Bobby Mueller
who showed me the ropes.
-This is the signal?
-That's the signal.
But things are a little
different these days.
Bobby passed away about
10 years ago,
so his son Wayne
is now running the joint.
I love when I talked to
your dad about the, uh,
James Beard Award.
In 2006, y'all got
a James Beard Award?
Uh, correct.
Well, I mean, that's it?
[ Laughs ]
Well...
That's kinda like a major thing.
Oh, yeah, we got that, too.
[ Laughs ]
What would your dad
have thought of that?
Ah, he'd have been flabbergasted
like the rest of us.
Yeah?
[ Laughs ]
One of the biggest,
most coveted awards
you can get in the food world,
and he's got it
by the ice tea machine.
[ Ding ]
I think the "Triple D" sign
gets a little bit more play
than the James Beard Award.
So, we're making the sausage?
Yep, we make it
right back there.
This is my father's recipe
from 1965.
What are we gonna do, look for
a needle in a haystack?
Spread it out.
Why, 'cause when we put the
seasoning on, you want it even?
-Right.
-So you buy fat?
-Buy fat, grind it up.
-Yes, sir.
Look how nice and -- I mean,
that's nice, good, white fat.
Now this is the seasoning?
-This is what sets it apart.
-Okay.
And you're gonna tell me
about this?
-No.
-No?
FIERI: And they're still not
spilling the secret.
Now you start the big
mixing process?
Right.
And then we're gonna
put this back in the grinder?
Yes.
I think you might wanna
think about, like,
an aerobics video,
you know,
"Making Sausage
with Bobby Mueller."
♪♪
Now you reach and you pull
and you reach
and you pull
and you reach and...
That's true.
Now, what does
the cold water do?
It just helps to mix it up so we
can get it through the stuffer.
-That's it.
-All right.
Now, do we measure it
as we link it?
Is that what your little block
is there for?
This wood block represents the
width of a slice of white bread
so that it can be
mobile food.
Just wrap it in that piece
of bread and go.
We offer it in three varieties.
That's regular, jalapeño,
and the chipotle.
And the chipotle.
Which one's your favorite?
I like all of 'em.
♪♪
Mmm.
That's great.
I was thinking
there might be something
like a chicken sun-dried tomato
coming out of here.
[ Laughs ] Not yet.
[ Laughs ]
The sausage they make --
not too fatty.
It's just beefy and it's got
some kick to it.
It's delicious.
WOMAN: We can't leave here
without the sausage.
It is absolutely wonderful.
FIERI: And if you can't make up
your mind, don't worry.
There's always
the sampler platter.
♪♪
WAYNE:
It's gonna include beef rib,
beef brisket, beef burnt ends,
our beef dip,
and all-beef sausage.
It's yummy.
-I love it.
-Potato salad, coleslaw,
and the whole nine yards.
Gotta get the plate.
♪♪
This is a sanctuary
for the barbecue community.
Yeah, it's crazy, isn't it?
Oh, brother, it is like...
And he had no idea.
Oh, gosh, it's so crazy.
This is really
an institution.
Do you recognize yourself
in being that much
of an icon of barbecue?
Uh, not really.
Just another barbecuer.
Just another barbecuer?
Yeah.
When you say it and people
who saw the show,
they're like,
"I've been there."
Like they made
the pilgrimage, you know?
WAYNE: Yeah.
♪♪
Wayne's grandfather and his dad
would be so proud of him.
♪♪
Everybody that's a fan is proud
of what you've done
and how you've continued
and kept up the consistency
and improved on the things
without changing.
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
-And that's delicious.
-I appreciate it.
-Thank you.
-I'll take 15 of those to go.
♪♪
That is totally what I'd call
all in the family.
And that Mueller family, well,
they sure know
how to make the most outta
staying old school
with just salt, pepper,
and smoke -- that's it.
Now, coming up...
Kyufte.
-Kyufte?
-Yeah.
...a funky spot in Vegas
specializing in Bulgarian
bites...
Where's this been
all my diet?
[ Laughs ]
...and international incidents.
[ Arguing in foreign language ]
We're having a little bit of a
cultural intervention right now.
Now, I think everybody
by now knows
that Vegas is home to
my alma mater UNLV,
which makes it a city that
I always have a great time in.
But when I was there
back in 2012...
Oh, my God!
[ Laughter ]
...it was everyone else
that was having a good time
because this
Eastern-European joint
was the scene of the ultimate
"Triple D" prank,
and I was the punchline.
You are dead and you're dead.
[ Laughter ]
The food coming out of the
kitchen was no laughing matter.
This is Forte.
♪♪
Stuffed peppers and ragu.
A friend of mine saw Forte
on "Triple D"
and she brought me here
and it's really change my view
of dining in Eastern Europe.
YOUNG WOMAN: If Bulgaria has
lots of food like this,
then I would definitely
would love to go to Bulgaria.
FIERI:
But you don't have to, because
that international flavor
is loud and proud
right here in Vegas.
And when I came by Forte
the first time,
that wasn't the only surprise
owner Nina Manchev, her dad,
and the crew
had in store for me.
Uh...
[ Speaking foreign language ]
We're having a little bit
of a cultural intervention
right now.
They told Guy that I don't speak
very good English.
[ With accent ] He --
he make by hand. Um...
That my father doesn't
speak very good English.
[ Speaking foreign language ]
What he's telling her
right now is,
"Don't share the family recipe."
Unh-unh.
Now he's storming off.
[ Speaking foreign language ]
Now, Neil, our P.A. jumps in,
and it's gonna be
battle royale.
[ Speaks foreign language ]
But --
[ Without accent ]
Yeah, but we've been here
for about 20 years,
so, you know,
we speak English pretty well.
What's up, man?
No way!
Yes!
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughing continues ]
That's all fun and games.
NINA: Everybody that comes
in mentions it,
and they just really enjoy it.
-Well, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
Don't think this is
gonna be easy on you today.
That's okay.
All right, let's --
what are we making?
Today we're gonna be making
two different styles
of the Bulgarian sausage,
which all go into
the Bulgarian mixed grill.
We're gonna be doing
kebapche and kyufte.
-"Kuvde"?
-Kyufte.
-Kyufte?
-Yeah.
The kyufte that's shaped
like a patty has fresh parsley,
red pepper, and some nice
seasonings in there.
All right, well,
that one's working.
-Next up?
-The kebapche.
That's ground pork sausage.
Like a piece of meat rope.
That is a platter.
♪♪
Where's this been all my diet?
[ Laughs ]
Very rich.
Each one has its own respective
different taste.
♪♪
Eastern Europe comfort food.
Outstanding.
Guy definitely helped
make our food relevant.
Bulgarian cuisine
is kind of untapped.
It was a blessing that he was
able to expose us
to a whole demographic
of people.
FIERI: And now,
she's exposing those people
to an even wider range
of cultural classics.
Stroganoff ragu, but instead
of the mushrooms
being a part of the sauce,
we do mushroom dumplings.
Saute the onion
with the mushrooms
and then add our mushroom
powder mix.
We use gyoza, and we put about
half a spoon
in the middle and pinch 'em.
And this becomes a wonderful
vessel for all the sauce.
Put them into our boiling
pot of water.
Less than a minute.
So the final step, we're gonna
assemble our stroganoff ragu.
Ground beef,
add a little bit of flour,
add our browned onion,
bay leaves, beef base, water.
Let it cook down
for a couple hours.
Add some sour cream,
and just mix it
until it's
a nice creamy texture.
♪♪
Fresh parsley.
Ragu?
WOMAN: It's these beautiful,
like, mushroom dumplings,
beef stroganoff on top,
and it's so savory,
it's so beautiful.
This is what I love
about "Triple D."
You come here and you get to
step out of your everyday food
and experience
something like this
that you've probably
never had before.
Thracian clay pots are up.
-Thracian?
-Thracian.
The Thracian clay pot.
Roasted bell pepper.
Any type of pepper or...
The red or the yellow ones
just for the color.
Green onion.
Feta cheese.
Tomato. Lukanka.
This is the Bulgarian
dry-cured charcuterie.
That is killer.
♪♪
Peppers, the bread,
the sauce, the cheese.
♪♪
Wow!
FIERI: But the clay pot
isn't the only thing
she's stuffing these days.
We're gonna make the stuffed
sweet peppers.
Chopped onions.
We're gonna add
our grated carrots.
We have our ground pork.
Break it down a little bit.
Dill, some garden savory.
Cooked rice.
And then we're ready
to fill our peppers.
About 15 minutes on 400 degrees,
and you're good to go.
♪♪
They're sweet, savory,
and light, but still filling.
Me, I can eat a whole plate.
I've eaten about
four pounds of killer...
-Lukanka.
-Exactly.
You gotta come meet this girl.
She's got it goin' on.
♪♪
And that's not all
she's got goin' on.
They've also added a market
and a bakery,
so you could take a little slice
of Bulgaria home with you.
Now, coming up...
Mmm.
I'm hitting a Hotlanta
hotspot...
He's happy now, you know?
[ Laughs ]
...that's known
for not changing a thing.
It would be like cheating
on this place.
[ Laughter ]
-Yeah!
♪♪
FIERI: On "Triple D,"
there are dives,
and then there are legends.
And this place in Midtown
Atlanta, it was both.
It was a legendary dive.
Nachos with chili.
It's big on tattoos,
it's small on change.
Same owner, same chef,
same spot in a strip mall.
This is The Highlander.
WOMAN:
It's always been an institution.
I like to call it my dirty bar.
They finally got recognized for
all the good work that they do.
Jeff's a really good guy.
He treats this place like it
is his home.
FIERI: That would be owner
Jeff Merback,
who opened this place
with a couple of buddies
back in 1992.
Why Highlander?
Brainstorming one night,
lot of beer,
and we ended up watching
the "Highlander" at my --
one of my -- one of -- one of --
You watched the "Highlander"?
I was right!
In the 11 years since
we were on "Triple D,"
very little changes around here.
Our decor is the same.
We still are punk rock,
heavy metal.
Ibrahim is still
running the kitchen.
Ice is your nickname?
Yeah.
'Cause your real name is?
Ibrahim Garba Jahumpa.
Oh, so let's just go with Ice.
Ice, yeah.
Now, we're gonna
make jerk chili?
-Yes.
-What makes it jerk?
Um, there's a jerk marinade
that we add to it.
I mean, just because
you're cooking it with me
doesn't make it jerk, right?
No, no, no.
Ground beef,
spicy Italian sausage, onions,
red peppers, green pepper.
I like the colors.
Now we add the kidney beans,
black beans,
and a few tomatoes.
This looks like about
the entire spice counter.
Almost.
We're just gonna Bermix
everything that's in here.
Now he's happy now, you know?
[ Whirring ]
We're mining for ore today!
Guy was very, uh,
enamored with that.
Whoo-ha!
[ Laughs ]
Get that in my bag.
After it broke and it had to be
replaced,
we kept it in the office
for a while
thinking we would find a way
to get it to Guy,
but we never could find
the address of Flavortown.
Look at that.
Mmm.
Gosh, it's good.
Great spice, great color,
great textures.
That's good chili.
I've always loved Ice's cooking.
He's always had a thing
for Jamaican food.
ICE: Jamaican curry goat
was on our special board,
and he was really excited
about seeing goat on there.
I'd walk right by here
and think, "Mmm, curry goat."
FIERI: I didn't get to eat it
back then, but yep,
you got it right --
nothing's changed.
Finally gonna make this
for Guy.
We're gonna add the olive oil,
the onions, garlic, allspice,
and we're gonna mix
all these in a bowl.
Thyme, Old Bay ground, parsley,
scallions, cumin, fresh ginger.
Now we can add
all the seasonings,
the Jamaican spicy curry,
tomato paste, coconut milk,
jerk seasoning,
scotch bonnet peppers.
We're gonna add the goat.
I'm gonna add the spiced rum,
butter, carrots.
Add a little bit of water.
Let it simmer for about
an hour and a half.
In the last 30 minutes,
I'm gonna add some potatoes.
Jasmine rice.
Scallions.
Curry goat with jasmine rice.
MAN: Nice. Thank you.
WOMAN: Very moist, tender.
It seems like it had been
cooked for hours and hours.
The curry's not too intense,
either.
Ice, baby, I'm tellin' ya.
It's like making a U-turn
in Flavortown.
Potatoes, hot.
FIERI: Of course, they do have
their standard bar bites,
but with a signature
Ice twist.
I've never seen mozzarella
sticks quite like his.
Sheeted egg pasta?
Brush it with a little bit
of the egg wash.
Just like that.
That's it, just one rollover?
-Yeah.
-Then in the bread crumb.
I like this.
Now we're gonna fry 'em?
Yeah.
Wow!
I'm impressed!
The sheet around it makes it
hold together,
gives it a nice texture.
That's tasty, man.
It's one of our
best sellers here.
FIERI: And he's got the fryer
working on overdrive,
with Southern staples
like corn fritters,
and his newest best seller,
fried chunks and pickles.
And it's just like it sounds.
Add the vinegar and water,
kosher salt and pickling spice,
sliced cucumbers, sliced garlic.
You're gonna add the habaneros.
Pour the brine
into the pickle bucket.
In a couple of days,
it's ready to go.
Bread the pickles.
It's flour, corn meal, paprika,
garlic powder,
onion powder, salt, and pepper.
And we're gonna do the chicken
chunks the same way.
And we're ready to drop it
in the fryer.
Chunks and pickles.
Serve it with a Sriracha ranch
and honey mustard sauce.
♪♪
Chunks and pickles.
It's an actual real chunk
of chicken.
Batter is very light.
Really tasty.
All the seasoning that you want,
a little bit of spice,
a lot of salt.
It's pretty much perfect.
♪♪
FIERI: There's always a party
at The Highlander.
-Yeah.
-Absolutely.
I dig it, man.
Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
No "Highlander II"
though, huh?
No.
It would be like cheating
on this place.
[ Laughter, cheers ]
I like their philosophy --
sometimes it's best not to mess
with a good thing.
Like at Louie Mueller's
in Texas,
where one family's
been busting out barbecue
the same way for 70 years.
And in Las Vegas, where
an Eastern-European eatery
is still cooking up
cultural classics.
Plus, of course, the joint
in Georgia that thrives
by staying a dive.
But I know what you're asking.
You're saying, "Hey, Guy,
what are all the other
'Triple D' joints up to?"
I don't know.
We'll have to find out next time
on "Triple-D Nation."
-That is brutal.
[ Laughter ]
I want you to understand,
ladies and gentlemen.
Just take a look --
just pan around here.
-Dead man, dead man...
[ Laughter ]
...already a dead man.
♪♪