You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy. That one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D' --
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
FIERI: But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking,
like on this trip...
Oh, that's good.
FIERI: ...in Vancouver, BC,
a modern-day diner...
Oh, all day long.
FIERI: ...pushing the limits
with their pancakes.
It's like a split-personality
breakfast.
FIERI: Plus...
♪ Da-da-dada, uh, mm ♪
FIERI:
...a rock-solid pizza parlor...
I want some spicy, hot
Lady ZaZa.
FIERI: ...going gangbusters
in Minneapolis.
West Coast.
Minnesota.
FIERI:
And in Austin, Texas...
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
...this barbecuer
is singing...
Here come the ribs!
...winging...
Pam, those are great.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
...and smoking me out.
Are you even there?
FIERI: Familiar faces,
new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
There is no way I come back
to Vancouver, BC,
and do not check
this joint out.
I mean, this is a "Triple D"
favorite.
The chef is a character.
The food's off the hook.
You're gonna love it --
the Red Wagon.
What happened to the awning?
♪♪
MAN: Two green-onion pancakes,
duck confit.
It's traditional diner food
done to perfection.
I'd say that it's definitely
become a Vancouver staple.
Like, more and more people
know about it,
and more and more people
want to try it.
It's a diner elevated.
It's up here.
FIERI: And the man who brought
this place to new heights --
that'd be French-trained chef
Brad Miller,
who's taken Red Wagon diners
on a wild ride
with new twists on old classics,
kind of like the Red Wagon rides
he took growing up.
So, you guys used to ride
in the Red Wagon?
-Yeah.
-This is the Red Wagon trio?
-That's us.
-Can you say it five times fast?
Red Ragon --
Red Wagon rider,
Red Wagon rider.
Wed Wagon wider?
No, that's -- see?
You sound like Elmer Fudd.
"Oh, that's wight.
I'm the Wed Wagon wider."
I'm looking for the owner.
Can you tell me if he's around?
I haven't seen him.
Yeah.
He's a little stockier guy.
He's got a bread.
It actually makes you
look younger.
[ Laughs ]
-How's biz?
-Not bad at all.
-Not bad, huh?
The pork belly's selling.
Those pulled-pork pancakes
are selling.
FIERI:
And I'll tell ya --
I'll never forget
those pulled-pork pancakes.
What are we gonna
start with?
Pulled-pork pancakes
with Jack syrup.
Why does that sound like
he made that
at about
4:30 in the morning?
A trimmed-down pork butt,
give it a generous rub.
You gonna let this rest at all,
or are we just ready to go?
36 hours, optimally,
in the fridge.
And then go into the smoker,
hitting it with the apple.
How much time
in the smoker?
Four to five hours.
We get her into a pan, douse it
with a little something.
You douse with
a little something?
We get a little beer
that we use on that.
In she goes.
Now you gonna wrap it?
Yeah.
We're gonna cover it up.
Pop it in the oven,
250, for how long?
Another
three to four hours?
-Yeah.
-And then go into the syrup?
Yep.
Exactly.
We got a liter
of light maple syrup.
Secret ingredient
over here for you.
Okay. Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
You're serious?
I am, yes.
And then we'll build
some pancakes.
-Let's roll.
-Cakes are working.
That's our pulled pork
right there.
-Now we're gonna hit it with...
-Barbecue sauce.
So, all this cooks up
together?
Yeah.
Cakes are almost ready here.
Build them right here
on the flat top.
Just lay down some pork.
We're gonna layer
these guys up.
That looks good.
There we have it --
pulled-pork pancakes.
And then just over the top.
Dig in.
Wow.
It's like a split-personality
breakfast.
Really nice
buttermilk pancake --
and, I mean, we're talking
thick and rich.
And the maple syrup,
with a little tinge
of that Jack
coming through.
Yep.
A little sweetness.
-Nice job, man.
-Thank you, sir.
Wow.
FIERI: But these days, he's got
an even swankier stack
for the a.m. crowd.
MILLER: Green-onion pancakes,
with duck confit.
So, if it wasn't enough
that you took us down
pancake and pork,
now you take us down
pancake and duck?
Exactly, yeah.
MILLER: We season our duck legs
with salt, sugar,
curing salt,
and peppercorns,
bay leaf, thyme, garlic,
and brandy.
And then we dip it
directly into the fat.
Then it sits overnight,
and then we put it into the oven
for about 2 1/2, 3 hours
and crisp it up in a pan.
To make our buttermilk pancakes,
we use eggs,
buttermilk, flour, salt,
and baking soda.
We just put them on the flat top
till they're golden on one side.
We sprinkle it
with green onions,
turn it over --
it's ready to go.
We put the the pancakes on,
duck confit on there.
We get a little arugula
tossed in sesame,
and our hoisin maple
that goes over to finish.
MAN: Two green-onion pancakes,
duck confit.
That's hoisin maple
right there, yes.
There's only a few people
in this world
that can put hoisin sauce
and maple syrup together.
[ Chuckles ]
It's Peking duck
with a scallion pancake.
Mm-hmm.
You know, like a Chinese
scallion pancake.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
You naturally get the sweet
from the hoisin.
Beautifully confit.
It's rendered
all the way down.
Tender meat.
Yeah, good.
Delicious --
I mean, delicious.
Thank you, sir.
I think I might like this
better than
the pulled-pork pancakes.
Well, yeah.
-I mean, seriously.
-I don't mind that at all.
MAN: It's really great to have,
like, Asian flavors
mixed with North American
traditional pancakes,
so adding the green onions
in there
with the hoisin maple syrup
is like a completely new
pancake experience.
You get the pancake
deliciousness,
and the duck confit
is unbelievable,
and that's, like,
a game changer.
How many are coming in
for bacon, eggs,
and hash browns,
and how many are coming in
for the sensational creations?
You know what?
We get a lot of just --
you know, they're coming in for
the standard bacon and eggs.
But, yeah, weekends -- stuff
like this definitely blows up.
-Someone says you're moving?
-We're moving --
just down the street that way,
about a block and a half.
How much bigger is
the new place?
About 20 more seats.
But a bigger kitchen,
better accommodations.
Bigger kitchen,
better all around.
I opened a little French bistro
as well --
Wagon Rouge,
so there go...
No. It's not called
Wagon Rouge.
-It sure is.
-I dig it.
All right,
what else you got?
We got a grilled cheese
tomato soup coming up.
So, old school.
This is nostalgia
with a twist.
MILLER:
Our grilled cheese is basically
a cheddar, Swiss, and goat.
We put it on a couple slices
of brioche.
Goat gives
a little tang to it.
Sear it in a pan
with a bit of butter,
into the oven,
and smoky tomato soup --
we smoke our tomatoes
for a couple of hours,
and we add a bouquet garni --
parsley, bay leaf, and thyme.
Sweat off a bunch of onions
with some garlic.
We put our tomatoes
into that, sauté,
blend it up with cream.
Tomato soup
in a little bowl.
You got a little basil oil
on there, croutons,
and slice
the grilled cheese in half,
put a little pickle spear
through it.
MAN: One grilled cheese,
smoky tomato soup.
-Oh, you get the goat cheese.
-Yeah.
Something as simple as a
grilled cheese and tomato soup,
but have it elevated in
the unique ways you do things.
-Yeah.
-It's dynamite, man.
This is just
kissed with smoke.
Yeah, we don't go
too heavy.
You still get the tomato.
The basil oil's
a nice little add.
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, all day long.
Even in Canada, you guys had
tomato soup and grilled cheese?
-Even in Canada.
-Delicious.
WOMAN: The soup has
a really nice smoked flavor.
The grilled cheese sandwich
is amazing.
It's ooey-gooey, cheesy -- very
tasty, very nice combination.
-That's done right.
-Thank you very much.
-I mean, congrats, buddy.
-Thanks, man.
-I'm happy for you.
-Thank you very much.
I'll come see you
at the new place.
-Please do. Yeah.
-It won't take me six years.
No.
I love those "Triple D"
Canadian joints.
I mean, it just goes
to show you --
Flavortown's reach goes
way beyond the borders.
Now, next up, I'm heading
to Austin, Texas,
where this barbecuer swears
that good bark...
Look at that --
great color on it.
...depends on good bark.
It's bad on pits,
but great on meat.
Well, this is gonna be
a new one for me.
FIERI: I was in Austin, Texas,
back in 2008,
so of course
I went sniffing around
for some real-deal barbecue,
and I could smell
the mesquite a mile away.
Whoa!
The food was legit, but, man,
it was smoky in there.
This is Green Mesquite.
♪♪
I really enjoyed the episode
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Green Mesquite is one of the
best barbecue places in Texas.
It's the barbecue version
of home cooking.
The mesquite wood
that they use --
it gives it a distinct flavor.
Three-meat plate.
FIERI: And it's the only kind of
wood owner Tom Davis will use.
DAVIS: For me, green mesquite
had the best flavor,
the most consistent flavor,
and as long as it was
less than a year old
after it was cut,
it's considered green.
So, does that give it
a snappier,
a little peppier bite
to it?
It's bad on pits,
but great on meat.
DAVIS:
Here we go on the pit.
Are you breathing
in the middle of this?
-Barely breathing.
-Like Aquaman.
I'm trying not to breathe,
actually.
This is gonna be
a new one for me.
Guy had never tried
pure mesquite-smoked food.
-Mmm.
-I suffer for my customers.
Yes, you do.
Are you even there?
The ribs --
give me the rubdown.
Okay, we got here --
You get it?
"Give me the rundown"?
"Give me the rubdown"?
Here we go.
We got brown sugar,
onion powder,
we got your garlic powder.
Kind of the usual suspects
to make a rub.
That's right.
Paprika, cayenne,
which I know you love.
Right.
You rub it in
really good.
You don't fool around.
You got it, use it.
Look at that --
great color on it.
That'll make a nice bark.
Now, how long are these
gonna go on for?
4 1/2 to 5 hours.
Here come the ribs!
Here come the ribs.
Okay, you want to
get yours?
Share and share not
alike.
You be Cher.
I'll be Sonny.
All right.
Let's go cut these and eat them.
Look at that.
They're just dripping
right out there.
Boy, they're juicy.
This is
the barbecue sauce?
Uh-huh.
Mmm.
Mmm!
Our barbecue sauce
at Green Mesquite --
we make it here.
I looked at the ingredients.
I said, "I can make this
the way I want."
So that's what we did.
Now, how do you do it?
No, no.
On top of the ribs, please.
My mother
might be watching.
What?
We're in barbecue country.
DAVIS: After "Triple D," we
expanded to two more locations.
We have three altogether now.
FIERI: Tom's also not manning
the smokers anymore.
For that cough-inducing duty...
It's horrible.
...Joe Reese has stepped up
to the plate,
and he's keeping the fires going
with newcomers,
like the loaded baked potato
stuffed with brisket.
We season it with black pepper,
kosher salt,
granulated sugar,
and dried red peppers.
Then we'll put it on the pit
and smoke it
for a minimum of 15 hours.
I'm gonna chop up some brisket
and mix it with barbecue sauce.
We have the baked potato,
and we'll add butter,
sour cream, cheese.
We'll add the chopped beef.
Stuffed baked potato.
MAN: The baked potato
with sour cream, cheese,
with the chopped beef --
it's a heck of a meal.
-Now tell me about wings.
-Margarine first, okay?
Just throw it over here
and just let it melt?
That's right.
The brown sugar next,
chili sauce after that.
-I'm gonna just stand back here.
-That's right.
'Cause the way you're
whisking and whipping...
Now some
regular hot sauce?
Louisiana Hot Sauce
right here.
What you do is
you smoke it first
for approximately one hour
at 200 degrees.
Really?
Now they're out of the smoker.
Now they go into the fryer.
For a minute and a half.
This is just gonna be
the crisp.
There we go.
Take my wing sauce, and kind of
pour it like that,
kind of shake them around.
FIERI: You scare me with that
winging and saucing.
DAVIS:
And there they are.
That's hot.
Mmm.
The wing is nice and tender,
a lot of great moisture
to it,
not too spicy.
That's a really good wing.
I'm interested in
trying one,
but I figured
I'd just get a big...
Pam, those are great.
[ Laughs ]
This is my wife, Lori.
And she did a good job.
-Aw.
-Say "bye-bye."
Bye-bye.
♪ Ba, ba, ba
Ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba ♪
And the boogaloo.
And you thought it was just
good brisket and wings.
FIERI: But chicken wings aren't
the only bird on the menu.
These days, you can also get
a smoked-turkey sandwich.
DAVIS: It's one of our most
popular items.
I eat it twice a week at least.
REESE: We're gonna start
with brining the turkey.
The brine consists of
kosher salt,
lemon pepper,
granulated sugar, and water.
What we're trying to do with
the brine is make it more juicy.
After we brine it,
season it with the lemon pepper,
we smoke this for three hours.
And now we're gonna make
a smoked-turkey sandwich.
Start with mayonnaise, lettuce,
tomato, red onion,
and pickles, slice the turkey,
served open face.
That flavor turkey
is smoky and very tender.
And it's just always
really flavorful and moist.
I love it.
There's one thing that I think
we're pretty sure on.
Uh-oh.
You have a love affair
with food.
-I love it.
-You love coming to work.
-I love coming to work.
-This is not even work, is it?
No, it's just fun.
It's home.
And a cameo by Lori?
Now, that's not something
that you see every day,
so you know the food
had to be good.
Now, coming up -- a pizza place
in Minneapolis...
This is gonna
blow your mind.
...pulling inspiration
from everywhere...
Oh, my gosh.
I'm a kimchi junkie.
...and piling it all
on the pie.
Without question,
this is way up there.
♪♪
There's nothing like pizza
from a wood-fired oven,
except maybe Korean-inspired pie
cooked in a French oven...
and maybe have it
in Minneapolis.
And since "Triple D" popped by,
they've opened two new joints
in the Twin Cities.
This is Pizzeria Lola.
Sweet Italian.
MAN: I'm a pizza lover and been
coming here since day one.
And I was actually
on that episode.
It's wonderful.
It's amazing.
It's opulent and delicious.
WOMAN: When it hit that
national spotlight,
it was really exciting
to see Ann's business grow,
but the quality stayed the same.
We have two Korean BBQs.
FIERI:
The Ann she's talking about?
That'd be Chef Ann Kim,
who found a way to marry
her mother's Korean recipes
with her love for New York pie.
All right.
Let's talk about the dough.
How are we gonna
start yours off?
KIM: We're gonna dump
the poolish in.
Look at that.
Next, we're gonna add
Italian flour
and then some more yeast,
cold water,
and last,
some Italian sea salt.
-I wanted to open a bakery...
-Yeah?
...and call it
the Yeastie Boys.
-I like it.
-West Coast.
[ Laughs ]
Minnesota.
Guy had the Lady ZaZa --
the pizza with the kimchi.
You think you're funny,
don't you?
I want some spicy, hot
Lady ZaZa.
We actually made the kimchi
together,
which is my mom's recipe.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm a kimchi junkie.
This is gonna
blow your mind.
We take our Napa cabbage,
warm salt water,
some Korean sea salt
in there.
And how long
is it gonna sit?
About three hours,
until it gets wilted.
Next.
We're gonna make the paste that
we're gonna put on the kimchi.
Start off with some
Korean chili powder...
-The magic Korean chili flakes.
-...which my mom imports for us.
Some fish sauce.
He likes it spicy.
Strong.
-No, it's fine.
Once you ferment it,
the flavors --
-That's awesome.
-Yeah.
You get the sweetness.
You get a little bit of that
shrimpiness coming through.
You get some of the chili.
Now we build the pie.
-Yes.
-Let's rock 'n' roll.
-All right.
On the base is red
California pear tomatoes,
some of this
Korean sausage,
that kimchi that
we made earlier,
the serrano peppers,
fresh scallion,
and then we finish it off
with sesame oil,
stick it in the oven.
Oh!
You should smell it!
And then
the soy-chili glaze.
And we top it off with toasted
black and white sesame seeds.
Look at that.
Wow! Got a little bit of sweet,
a little salt.
You got some crunch.
Without question,
this is way up there.
FIERI:
But if kimchi's not your thing,
she's got another pie inspired
by her mother's cookbook --
the Korean BBQ pizza.
The Korean BBQ happens to be one
our number-one-selling pizzas.
It starts with
the Korean barbecue short ribs
that have been marinated
in soy sauce, garlic.
But the kicker to this marinade
is pear,
and that adds a really nice,
full sweetness,
but it also helps
break down the short ribs.
We'll let it marinate
about 24 hours,
and then it'll be ready to cook
in the wood-fired grill.
Then from there, we start off
with our handmade dough,
shredded whole-milk mozzarella,
thinly sliced scallions,
Korean barbecue short ribs.
And now it's ready to go.
FIERI:
Oh, but it's not done yet.
We finish it off with arugula
that's tossed in this spicy
gochujang vinaigrette
and sprinkled
with sesame seeds.
♪♪
-Here's your Korean BBQ.
-Oh, yummy.
MAN:
You got some greens in there,
then the meat is, like, velvet-y
with a little bit
of spice in it.
It's a little sweeter
flavor profile,
and that's kind of
something unique,
I feel like,
to Korean barbecue.
The crust is unbelievable here.
I don't know what they do.
They must do some sort
of voodoo magic back there
when they put it in the oven,
but it's the best in town
by far.
FIERI:
You call it a pizza oven.
Me?
I call it wood-fired oven.
You've got different heats
going on.
She won't put the pizza
in the same spot again.
If she puts it
right back there,
it's just a little bit
of a temperature drop,
and that could make
all the difference.
How much was the oven?
Probably more than that car
out there.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I like it.
FIERI:
Well, I'm not going anywhere,
'cause coming up,
Ann's popping a pie in the oven
so off the rails...
Don't go through the yolk!
...I had to call in
for reinforcements.
ZIMMERN: You may want to man up
and just go for it.
I could kiss you.
[ Laughs ]
-♪ Da-da-dada, uh, mm ♪
-[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Back in 2012,
I rocked out to Ann Kim's
Korean-inspired,
French-oven-baked
pizza joint in Minneapolis.
Her greatest hits included
My Sha-Roni! and Lady ZaZa.
But one track almost had me
turning the dial.
Egg pizza.
We have a pizza called
the Sunnyside
with two sunny-side-up eggs.
FIERI: And we all know
how I feel about eggs,
so I figured
if I'm gonna step out of
my culinary comfort zone --
ha! -- I'm dragging in
one of Minneapolis'
favorite culinary daredevils,
Andrew Zimmern.
And the Sunnyside is
one of his favorite pies.
Pecorino Romano.
-It's Pecorino Romano.
Then we go down
with some leeks.
And what was the cream?
-Heavy cream.
-Just regular heavy cream.
-Yep.
FIERI: Now we're going down
with some --
It's guanciale,
actually.
-Guanciale. Oh.
-Guanciale -- cheeks.
Hey, right in there, baby.
I'm telling you --
I can't believe they don't try
to harvest me every winter.
KIM: So, he pretty much dared
Guy to eat this pizza,
and I know he hates eggs.
I know he in particular
hates runny eggs.
Through the yolk.
-Don't go through the yolk!
ZIMMERN:
This is the best part.
You may want to man up
and just go for it, my friend.
And there you go --
the Sunnyside.
Just go for it.
Oh, that is hot.
You can do it.
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
So, everybody knows,
in "Triple D" world,
I don't like eggs, but I will
actually have to say, this...
Pretty darn good, right?
...that's pretty dynamite.
I'm so happy right now,
I could kiss you.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: But for the pizza purist,
Ann's got an old-school pie
called La Creme --
and I do mean old-school.
She's crushing those tomatoes
with her hands.
The La Creme is actually
one of our simplest pies.
We'll take our pizza dough,
and then we'll top it
with the rustic tomato sauce,
a little bit of olive oil,
salt, heavy cream, fresh basil,
and then it's ready
to go into the oven.
♪♪
We finish with a little bit
of olive oil
and Parmigiano-Reggiano.
And here's your La Creme.
I'm kind of
a pizza traditionalist,
so I just love a good pizza
that has a great sauce.
That cream that they put
in there
kind of brings it all together.
WOMAN:
It looks pretty simple,
and then
you put it in your mouth,
and it's this explosion
of flavor.
Do you have any tattoos?
No, I don't.
I could get one.
[ Laughs ]
I like the way you roll.
"You ever been
in a street fight?"
"No, but I might be
looking for one,
'cause you know
where I roll from.
Yeah!"
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Since then, we've expanded
and opened up Hello Pizza,
which is more of my East Coast,
New York-style pizzeria,
and most recently Young Joni,
which is an all-wood-fired-
cooking restaurant.
MAN: Each serve
different kinds of pizzas,
but the crust is the consistent
ingredient in all of them.
This has been off the hook.
I will be back.
Thank you.
-Thank you.
♪♪
Growing their menu
and their footprint,
the nation just keeps
getting bigger,
and that's why I love hitting up
the old-school joints,
like the Vancouver spot
dishing out diner classics
and blowing up boundaries,
to the legendary barbecue place
in Texas
where it's understood
that it's all about good wood,
and the pizzeria in Minnesota
cranking out crazy concoctions
that'll keep you
coming back for more.
We got plenty more places
to pop into,
and we'll see you next time
on "Triple D Nation."
Have you ever been on
national [laughs] television?
-Yes, I have.
-You have?
Yes.
Have you ever been
on the Food Network?
-I have.
-[ Laughs ] How red are you?
[ Laughing ] Okay, guys.
Please go away.
Oh, my God.
[ Laughs ]