You know, people are asking me
all the time --
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all...
This is ridiculous,
dude.
...but it turns out
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip,
in Vancouver, Canada...
Ta-da!
...off-the-hook Asian...
I can't shove it
in my face fast enough.
...done the authentic way...
What's this snake dance
you got going?
King Kong.
Did you just go King Kong
on me?
Green chili tacos,
ladies.
FIERI:
...a sibling-run restaurant
in Phoenix...
Do you get along?
-No.
-Not all the time.
FIERI: ...taking a page
from their mother's cookbook.
That's up there with some
of the best I've ever had.
And in Atlanta, Georgia...
Smoked wings up.
...a twin-brother
tag team...
Who's who, now?
...treating their customers
to some true Texas taste.
That is as Texas as it comes.
That's Flavortown 101,
ain't it?
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So I'm here
in Vancouver, Canada.
We just got done shooting
"Triple D."
And you know what that means --
I got to go visit
some of the OG joints.
Now, we came to this place
back in 2012.
They had one location,
and they did $1 million
a year in sales.
Now they're doing $8 million
in sales.
Well, that's what happens
when the residents
of Flavortown show up.
This is the Peaceful Restaurant.
♪♪
Guys, started
Thousand Chili Chicken.
Well, I saw Guy on
"Triple D" at Peaceful,
and the food looked amazing --
fresh ingredients,
made from scratch.
I've been coming for
at least 10 years.
It's such an amazing menu
and so many things that
you don't find anywhere else.
FIERI: 'Cause no other place
has Charlie Huang...
Ding,
cool noodles up.
...whose dad taught him
to cook back
in the Shanxi Provence
of China.
There's certain places
that I get to visit
that I really want
to make sure I come back,
and I can't believe --
How many years has it been?
It's been just about
6 1/2 years.
Yeah, thank you.
Thank you coming again.
I' so happy to see you.
But when I was there
the first time,
I was happy to be hands on with
Charlie's hand-made noodles.
This is the main event.
Like this.
♪♪
He spins it one way,
then he spins it the other way.
♪♪
He's just continuing to make
more and more strands.
This is thebomb.com.
Look at that!
Awesome.
Okay,
but now your turn.
Your turn.
♪♪
I show him how to do it,
but, eh...
[ Laughs ]
No good.
Let me show you.
Go this way.
Not this way.
See?
Strong man.
King Kong.
Did you just go King Kong
on me?
The whole experience
was crazy.
And I still don't know
how to make the noodles.
Really?
I'm still terrible at it.
So now we take them over
to boiling water...
Until inside's
cooked and firm.
Great chew.
Okay,
hot wok, hot oil...
Now we go into veggies.
Jalapeño.
Gonna be spicy.
Teaspoon of cumin,
red chili flake...
...a little salt.
Back in with the veg,
in real high heat
right now.
Nice!
♪♪
Mmm.
Let me see.
How do you do it?
♪♪
You don't see that every day
on "Iron Chef."
I can't shove it in my face
fast enough.
What do you got new?
What's new and exciting?
Here we are.
Okay.
Let me show you.
Cold noodles.
Cold noodles salad?
Yeah.
I don't think I've ever had
in a Chinese restaurant
a cold noodle dish.
♪♪
Whoa, there's a little heat
in that.
Still tasty, right?
Delicious.
See?
♪♪
Mmm, good.
Oh.
Thank you very much.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Ta-da!
WOMAN: That particular noodle
has great chew to it,
great flavor, and it holds up
well with the sauce.
WOMAN #2: It was really light,
it was really bright,
and the noodles here
are spectacular.
I want to eat
everything on the menu.
FIERI: And when I was there
before, believe me, I tried.
Now what are we making?
Beef roll.
Okay.
We're gonna
cook the beef first.
Yeah, pot of hot water.
And what kind of beef
is that?
Beef shank.
Beef shank, okay.
Then we put the --
Star anise...
Star anise, yeah.
...red hot chili peppers,
cinnamon...
Cinnamon, clove...
...licorice root.
All this just
for the meat?
Yeah.
Flavorcity.
Green onion, ginger.
♪♪
Ginger.
Oh, yeah, go ahead.
Sharp.
Yeah!
Yeah, it's sharp.
[ Whispering ]
Put this in the car.
He won't know.
Thanks.
Sugar.
[ Normal voice ]
Sugar. Great.
Yeah.
Pieces of rock sugar.
Rock sugar?
What a crazy flavor
this is gonna have.
And we let this go
for four hours to simmer...
Yeah, yeah.
...with the lid on?
Yes. I like a
cold beer, cold beer.
We'll have a cold beer?
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
Four hours, four hours.
Wait for four hours.
Yeah, we come back
little later -- four hours.
Little bit.
Okay, let me cover.
Let me cover this.
Okay.
All right.
Let's go.
We'll see you
in a little bit.
Have a beer.
FIERI: Coming up...
Where's my knife?
Oh.
The verdict on the
never-had-before beef roll...
...and...
Szechuan
Thousand Chilli Chicken.
Szechuan Thousand...
Thousand.
...I'm gonna find out if that's
as dangerous as it sounds.
Is there any chicken
in there?
'Cause that looks
like all chili.
♪♪
Welcome back to
Peaceful Restaurant
here in Vancouver, Canada.
Hanging out with my buddy
Charlie,
who's been nice enough
to teach me the art of...
Noodles.
...noodles!
FIERI: And back in 2012,
he was also cranking out
killer creations
I've never had,
like the crispy Beef Roll.
Next...
Where's my knife?
Oh...
[ Whispering ]
Put this in the car.
He won't know.
[ Normal voice ]
Over there, I think.
Oh, oh, thank you.
[ Whispering ]
Close.
Chop beef.
[ Whistles ] Mmm.
You pick up the star anise,
you get a little bit
of the licorice --
mmm, it's tender as can be.
Roll it...
Chinese burrito.
...then you cut.
Ready?
♪♪
Crispy, right?
Yeah.
Crispy crazy!
Mmm.
Back then, Charlie was churning
out off-the-hook Asian food
from his one location,
but things are
a little different these days.
Now how many restaurants?
Five.
Five?
And another two coming.
Another two coming.
Seven restaurants.
This year.
Oh, so lucky I've got
kind of a chance
to show our home-style food.
♪♪
If there's one type of food
that I am a complete junkie for,
it is Asian food
and, particularly...
pan-fried dumpling.
Yeah, thank you.
That's what
I'm talking about!
Ground pork...
Ground pork.
...salt, sugar,
soy sauce.
White pepper.
Ginger,
green onion, bok choy...
Love bok choy.
Okay, and we start
making the dumplings?
Sure.
Fantastic.
You follow me, okay?
I'm gonna try.
What's this snake dance
you got going?
Yours looks like
a cobra.
Mine looks like
it ate a gopher.
Pretty good.
Okay.
Hold like this...
...then twist.
Okay.
It's not coming off
so right.
All right, now...
Okay.
...hang on a second.
Okay...
Okay, like that.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
This...sucks.
Now what?
You have to put the filling
into the dough.
Use two fingers...
And I go like this?
Yeah.
And I pinch in.
It's grab and pull?
Yeah, yeah.
Look at that.
Lots better.
Huh?
Yeah!
Okay.
We'll add water.
Now we cover it,
and we steam it.
Okay, ready?
♪♪
My God.
My God!
Tender but crispy.
The meat --
nice and juicy.
Oh, my God.
Are you hungry?
Who are you talking to?
They're hungry.
♪♪
He's trying to take
over the show now.
What else?
What else is new?
Szechuan
Thousand Chilli Chicken.
Szechuan Thousand...
Szechuan
Thousand Chilli Chicken.
...Chili Chicken.
Here we are.
Is there any chicken
in there?
'Cause that looks
like all chili.
Thousand Chili Chicken is
traditional
northern Chinese food.
It's 1,000 chilli, chicken,
green onion, salt.
♪♪
How do you eat it?
Just put it into --
I understand I put it in the
mouth part, Charlie, but...
but you're supposed
to eat the chili?
Yeah.
This?
Well,
it's not really hot.
You see all those chilies
in there,
and you want to think it's gonna
be smoking hot, but it's not.
Mmm.
What is this, garlic?
That's right.
[ Chuckles ]
Delicious.
Excellent dish.
It's intimidating
'cause you see just a plate
of bold, bright red chilies,
but it's got a wonderful --
like a tingling heat.
It's actually really tasty.
WOMAN: The chicken
is crispy, spicy.
It's really great.
When are you gonna open up
a location in California?
Any time.
Congratulations.
See you there.
Yeah, see you there.
♪♪
Listen, Charlie,
don't tease me.
What I wouldn't give for you
to come south of the border.
Up next, we're heading
back to the States...
Oh, that's good!
...to a spot where a couple
of Texan twins...
Get after it, Zorro!
...are bringing Lone Star
barbecue to Atlanta.
Oh, my gosh,
that's good!
♪♪
Now, I've always been down
with real-deal barbecue,
especially when I'm cruising
through the South.
And this place in Atlanta,
Georgia, is just plain smoking.
All right, folks, I've got
some beef brisket here.
Texas-style taste served up by
"Triple D's" first set of twins.
You can bet it doubles down
on delicious.
This is Fox Bros. Bar-B-Q.
♪♪
I got some wings.
MAN: We saw Fox Bros.
on "Triple D."
It's excellent barbecue --
best in Atlanta.
If we want good barbecue,
this is where we come.
Smoked wings up.
Justin and Jonathan are
legends here in Atlanta.
FIERI: Nope,
you're not seeing double.
That's Justin
and Jonathan Fox --
just a couple of Texan twins
who wanted to share their love
for good ole
Lone Star barbecue.
Who's who, now?
Jonathan...
Justin.
How do you know
these cats?
I've been coming here
for years.
That's right. I brought
my buddy,
racing-analyst and fellow
car-junkie Rutledge Wood,
who's addicted to Fox Bros.
Rutledge is a big fan,
big supporter.
What does Rut like to eat
when he comes in?
-The short rib.
-Oh, my gosh, the short rib,
the poppers are insane --
Everything's great here.
So what are we gonna make
today?
Our brisket burger.
All right, let's do it.
JONATHAN: This is a
certified Angus beef.
Trim down this fat
just a little bit.
When you're using CAB,
certified Angus beef,
you're starting
with great clay.
♪♪
I get it.
'Cause you love the movie
"Ghost."
I totally get
the pottery reference.
That was a great one, man.
You're really good
at this.
You are really good
Having Guy here and having
Rutledge involved,
the two of them
playing off each other,
it was like
a tennis match.
Can we make some
already?!
I immediately regret
the call.
"Hey, I heard you're coming
to Atlanta!"
FIERI: Go ahead.
Get after this.
So, yeah, we're just gonna
season our brisket
with our salt
and pepper seasoning.
Brisket with salt and pepper --
That is as Texas as it comes.
So now we're gonna go
to the smoker?
We're gonna go
to the smoker.
Great.
We cook it overnight 10
to 12 hours at 200, 205 degrees.
All right,
let's make a burger.
So we're gonna take
this brisket...
Oh, my gosh,
that's good!
Get after it, Zorro!
Pimento cheese patty,
couple pickles,
some of our peppered bacon,
tomato, onion.
So that's a chopped beef
sandwich -- called it a burger.
Called it a burger.
I like it.
♪♪
Oh,
super-tender brisket.
And adding the veggies
on top of it
brings that burger element
to it.
Mmm.
That's Fox Bros.
right there.
FIERI: And they're not letting
any of that brisket go to waste.
JONATHAN:
We're making brisket chili.
It was cold and I was like,
"It's a perfect day for chili."
So we took some leftover brisket
and made some chili.
Start off with diced white
onion, seeded jalapeños,
minced garlic,
a little salt, black pepper.
Part of making this
a Texas red brisket chili,
we've got some stewed
tomatoes in liquid,
tomato paste,
pork stock, adobo sauce,
chili powder,
chipotle powder,
garlic powder, onion powder,
cumin, a little sugar.
Now that it's cooked down
this far,
we're gonna add
the magic ingredient --
our chopped brisket.
So we've got a paper boat here
filled with some of
our favorite corn chips.
We're gonna fill it up with some
of this beautiful brisket chili,
we're gonna add a mix
of cheddar cheese
and jalapeño jack cheese,
diced onions, jalapeños.
And here we go.
Probably the best chili
you could have
because it has
the brisket in it,
and then you have the
crunchiness, and it's just...
It's a go-to.
The smokiness of the chili
with the salt
is really
a great flavor combination.
I think I can just punch
my ticket to --
What's that city you always go
to with all the good tastes?
That's Flavortown 101,
ain't it?
There you go.
That's it.
FIERI: They're also frying up
a bunch
of barbecue-inspired bites,
like these jalapeño poppers.
JONATHAN: We have our beautiful
pork butt here,
so we're gonna take this rub and
liberally coat this pork butt.
FIERI: And Rutledge and I got
the rundown on that rubdown.
JUSTIN: A little salt,
black pepper, onion powder,
garlic powder,
a little chili powder...
FIERI: Okay.
...paprika.
Hang on. What is this, Rutledge,
before he does it.
Ooh, this is one of my
favorite things you do.
Let me see if I can do it
the way Guy does it.
No, no, no.
Mmm, that tastes like a --
mmm -- little bit of --
a little bit of cumin.
A little bit of -- mmm --
is that coffee?
What is it?
I don't know what that is.
Ancho chili?
Yeah.
A little ancho chili.
JONATHAN: We're gonna cook it
for up to 10 to 12 hours,
about 200, 225 degrees.
Now we're ready
to take them home.
We're gonna take fresh jalapeño
that we fried,
fill it up with some
of this pulled pork.
This is a mix of cream cheese,
cheddar,
and jalapeño jack cheese.
We got a little flour here,
a little egg wash, some panko.
We just pop them down here
three to four minutes,
serve it up with a little
homemade ranch dressing --
good to go.
Jalapeño poppers
in the window.
MAN: The barbecue in it as well
as the cheese --
It melts together very nice.
It's the perfect mix of salty
and cheesiness and sweetness,
and it's a great start
to an awesome meal.
♪♪
JUSTIN: Being a part
of the "Triple D" family,
it was a great experience.
People see you
in random locations,
and they know you
from somewhere.
It never gets old.
Y'all come back, now.
Y'hear?
[ Laughs ] Peace!
♪♪
FIERI: You know what else
never gets old?
Hearing how much these places
are killing it.
Those guys have opened
three new joints around Atlanta.
And speaking of blowing up
around town...
Enjoy.
...coming up, another place
multiplying
their real estate...
WOMAN:
Green chili pork tacos.
...but this one's
upping the ante
on authentic Mexican
all over Arizona.
Who needs it in the taco?
I just want it like that.
♪♪
Right now, we're taking a trip
back to Phoenix, Arizona,
to a joint run by six siblings,
serving up real-deal Mexican.
WOMAN: I got a pozole
in the window!
Now, they've been building on
their dad's dreams and recipes
to create a taco empire
all around town.
This is Los Taquitos.
♪♪
Green chili tacos.
In Arizona, we're looking
for authenticity
in our Mexican food,
and Los Taquitos has that here.
Once Guy came here,
this place just took off.
I need a green chili
pork burrito, pozole.
It's a family affair --
all great chefs, excellent food.
FIERI: That's because
the fab five Ochoa sisters,
along with their brother,
learned to cook
authentic Mexican
from their parents who had
a taco truck in the '80s.
You're the official owner,
you're the head chef...
Yes.
...and you are
all working together.
Yeah.
Do you get along?
-No.
-Not all the time.
When Guy came here, he did an
amazing job back there, cooking.
They had a great time.
Blah-blah-blah-blah.
We're making our carnitas.
FIERI: So that's
a pork shoulder.
Trim a little bit
of the fat off the top?
I think that's enough.
You think that's enough?
That's enough.
Okay.
Gonna add our two
cinnamon sticks, garlic,
salt, condensed milk...
Some condensed milk,
really?
Mm-hmm.
Cola.
Some soda?
What's going on here?
We have our own recipe.
Little bit of water,
cover it.
Two hours until it just
falls apart.
So, not cooked
in the manteiga...
No.
...like I do.
[ Laughs ]
How is the flavor so great
and there's no oil?!
Who needs it in a taco?
I just want it like that.
You need to try the taco.
Get our tortillas --
you have to spank them,
make sure they're well done.
♪♪
Mmm.
Good?
No.
They're not good.
They're awesome?
That's up there with
some of the best I've ever had.
I remember mentioning
that we sell 3,000 tacos a week.
Since "Triple D," now we sell
like over 8,000 tacos a week.
FIERI: The tacos may be
on the Billboard's Top 10,
but this plate
is no one-hit-wonder.
These days, they're popping
that pork into the green chili.
We had a lot of customers asking
if we had green chili pork,
so we're like,
"You know what,
my mom makes really good
green chili pork -- why not?
Let's throw it in there."
We have our California pepper,
poblano pepper, jalapeños.
So we're gonna blend
all this up.
The chilies give it
a little kick.
We're gonna add it to our pork
that we already have cooking.
Now we're gonna add our
cilantro, then our tomatillos.
This is like
the main ingredient.
So, then we add our comino.
I say "comino,"
but they say "cumin."
Some comino.
Or cumin.
Cu-- Mm-hmm.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
And then we let it boil
for 30 minutes.
♪♪
Now we're gonna fry
our Anaheim chilies.
♪♪
We use our green chili pork
in a burrito,
bowl, enchiladas, and taco.
Green chili pork tacos.
The flavors are amazing.
It wasn't too spicy.
The meat is super soft,
onions were crispy,
so they kind of balance
each other out.
The pork was juicy,
it was moist, just spiced enough
to give you that tang.
After the show aired,
it became a zoo in here.
♪♪
We were so overwhelmed
'cause it was only us sisters.
Pork tacos!
We've opened four locations --
North Phoenix,
Chandler, Arcadia,
Phoenix airport.
MAN: I've been
to every one of them,
and the food is excellent,
every single store.
FIERI: I mean,
they've talked about
having demonstration kitchens
in a lot of restaurants.
This is one of those restaurants
they definitely should.
Love it.
She'll agree.
Is there no limit to how far
the "Triple D" nation will grow?
Like the Asian joint
in Vancouver
blowing up six times over,
the Lone Star barbecue spot
in Georgia
that's four locations deep,
and the Mexican diner
with five joints around Arizona.
And we'll check in
on some more next time
on "Triple D Nation."
You can tell if it's really good
just by smelling it.
No! No!
Oh, can you?
Let me smell it!
I got ChapStick
on my nose!