Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Come on.
...we're going
from the bomb breakfast...
There you go!
...to outrageous burgers...
Crazy!
...and dynamite desserts...
You got an issue.
And that issue's delicious.
...like sugar and spice
in Chico...
How would
you attack this?
...a plethora of pie
in Vancouver.
That really embarrasses
a lot of pies.
Plus, in Washington state...
Rye-t on!
[Right]
...baking plus beef equals
a crushing combination.
You're putting monster-truck
tires on a Bentley.
Wow!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in wonderful
Chico, California,
about two hours
north of Sacramento.
Now, you know what we don't see
a lot on "Triple D"?
Breakfast joints.
Oh, we've got them,
but people really
get passionate about them.
We had a lot of folks tell us
about this place.
You see, this server's
going to college,
and she's working here
at this joint
and eventually buys
the whole thing out.
You got to love it.
All-American town
with an all-American story
and some rocking food.
This is the Sin of Cortez.
Double happiness, up!
You always know it's gonna be
fresh, hot, delicious.
Paleo breakfast.
MAN: This is like coming
to your best friend's
that knows how to cook.
FIERI: And that good buddy
is Danielle Ius,
who has been feeding folks here
at her restaurant
365 days a year.
Why is everybody in such
a frenzy about Sin of Cortez?
People are used to
the greasy spoon,
and we came here,
we made everything fresh.
How did you get involved
in this?
I was a waitress.
And you have
worked your way
through this place
to where you now own it?
Yes.
Come on!
Blueberry cornmeal pancakes.
Danielle's really taken
breakfast to a whole new level.
French toast.
WOMAN: Thank you.
Cortez French toast is
one of my favorites.
it's not your usual Texas toast.
It's got cinnamon
running through it.
It's delicious.
We're making
our Cortez French toast
with our house-made
cinnamon bread.
Everything in this building,
we bake.
So, here we've
got our yeast rising.
That looks like when somebody
doesn't know how to
do the laundry
and they put in too much soap.
We'll start with oil.
Well, that party ended.
And now the egg?
We're gonna take our flour,
put it in our mixer.
I mean, I'm no baker,
but the 2 cups on the floor
probably should stay
in the bowl.
Well, that's the sin
of Cortez.
Salt, sugar, shortening.
Is this gonna
make it all in?
We're gonna stir
little bits at a time.
So, we let this mix,
let it proof.
Yep.
Now we're gonna make
the cinnamon mixture.
Okay.
So, we're gonna start
with softened butter,
brown sugar, cinnamon.
Cinna-minna-minna-minna-mon?
And then we're gonna slowly
add the bread crumbs in.
All right,
how many ounces?
2 pounds.
87,000 ounces.
I rounded up.
Fill a whole bunch
of the cinnamon mixture.
Whoa!
More sugar?
It's a cinnamon roll?
Voilà.
Nicely done.
Were gonna put it in the oven
at 350 for 40 minutes.
That's a big loaf.
Our batter's a little bit
more milk heavy than others.
I'm going to use eggs,
chocolate, brown sugar, milk.
You are
very milk heavy.
Let me see this
cinnamon-roll monster.
I just eat it like it is,
I mean...
And this is
a number-one seller?
One of the top ones.
We make our own
fresh puree with fruit,
and then you sugar it.
♪♪
So, I'm not a big
breakfast person,
nor am I
a big sweets person.
When I heard that you were doing
this cinnamon French toast,
I thought, "It's gonna be
too much for me."
You dumped in
all the sugar,
and then you dumped
in more sugar,
but what it's not
is too much.
It's delicious.
There's a lot of things that
shouldn't be working
that really do, like the extra
milk inside of the batter.
The density of the bread
is such that it really
does need the milk,
and then it cooks
on the flat top,
it kind of steams it
so it becomes nice and light.
If you like French toast,
it doesn't get much
more creative than that.
My youngest son loves cinnamon
rolls, loves French toast.
Package deal
right here, man.
French toast being plated.
It's thick. It's fluffy.
The adage goes
"Just like my mom made."
Well, no. This is a lot better
than my mom made.
Rancho verde.
WOMAN: We love coming here.
It's a really nice
family establishment.
FIERI: And it became a key
community gathering place
when ravaging fires
hit nearby in 2018.
One of the reasons
that we're here
is it was highly recommended
by the Rock family.
I know that you folks lost
your house,
and in the middle
of all of that,
you were taking care
of other people
and helping my team
when we came in to town
to support the first responders
and the evacuees.
So, why did you recommend
that I come to this location?
The people are great.
The food is amazing.
It's very consistent.
It's really good.
What's next on the menu?
Dragon potatoes.
The dragon potatoes
are my favorite.
It's beautiful.
Like a garden on top of the most
savory potatoes and pork.
There's some jalapeños
in there, hence the dragon.
Khh!
Yes.
How do you make
your dragon?
Wahhhh!
There you go.
That's quite a scary,
little dragon now, isn't it?
Scary, little dragon,
yes, that's me.
I'm going to butcher
our boneless pork butt
to make carnitas
for our dragon potatoes.
We'll do some bay leaves...
pepper, salt...
cumin, garlic...
yellow onion,
guajillo chilies.
Cook it for four hours
at 350 degrees.
Next step.
Black beans.
All right.
As soon
as it begins to boil,
we add the rest
of the ingredients --
salsa we make in-house,
cilantro, a ton of garlic,
yellow onions, chili powder,
cumin, oregano, chili flakes...
Kitchen sink.
...bay leaves, basil, salt.
And how long's this
gonna cook now?
45 minutes,
till they're tender.
Okay, next step.
Crispy rosemary potatoes.
We soft boil these.
[ Sizzling ]
Start with putting margarine
on the grill
and start squishing them.
The old crumble smash.
New culinary technique
we haven't seen on
"Triple D" before.
Fresh rosemary,
coarse ground pepper.
The trick is
with these potatoes,
you do not touch them.
You do not.
Once they're golden brown,
you flip them. That is it.
Carnitas, crisp it up.
And the jalapeños
on there?
Steam those just a bit.
[ Grunting ]
Ah-how!
Rosemary potatoes, beans,
carnitas and jalapeños, cheese,
tomatoes, scallions, cilantro,
avocado sauce, sour cream.
We gonna take
our tortilla.
A hurricane went
through here.
Dragon potatoes.
How would you attack this?
You smush it all together.
♪♪
I don't know that I've found
many places in the travels
of "Triple D"
quite like this.
This is a gigantic deconstructed
carnitas burrito,
but you take time
to touch everything,
make sure it's done right.
This, for a guy that
doesn't like breakfast,
is exactly the kind of breakfast
I'd like to eat.
Dragon potatoes, up.
Dragon potatoes have a nice
kick, just enough jalapeño.
There's slow roasted pork
just the way I like it.
When you mix that all up
in the spice, it's fantastic.
Come and get it.
MAN: I've been coming here
for 15 years.
It's just about as good
as it gets.
It just makes you feel at home.
I'm very inspired.
Came here as a waitress,
been running the show.
You have a huge following
of people that love you.
The food is unique, spicy,
crazy, delicious.
I'm pretty impressed.
Well done.
FIERI: Up next, a scratch spot
in Richland, Washington...
Here we go.
...getting gorgeous
with their salmon...
It tastes even better
than it looks.
...and crazy creative
with a familiar favorite.
That right there is really one
of the most remarkable burgers
I've had in "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here in the southeast
part of Washington State,
in an area known as Tri-Cities.
Let's see, it's Pasco.
It's Richland and Kennewick.
Now, this area right here
is a mecca for agriculture,
and I hear about this bakery
where they're really using
the bounty of the county,
scratch-making their goods,
and they're doing it, like,
right in the middle
of the dining room.
This is Ethos Bakery & Café.
Stuffed mushrooms,
chorizo burger!
Ethos has elevated the quality
of restaurant offerings
here in the Tri-Cities.
SERVER:
Shrimp and grits.
Amazing food.
Some of the best baked goods
you can get in the region.
Got a parm chicken.
Angela is full of surprises.
FIERI:
Like what Angela Kora was before
becoming a restaurant owner.
Mechanical engineer.
You were
a mechanical engineer?
Yeah.
Decided to become a baker,
you know,
'cause people do that.
It's the same thing.
Exactly.
And she's engineered her
scratch-made menu
around fresh and local fare.
This area has such
strong resources,
and to get to showcase
them is amazing.
I have a salmon gravlax.
In the Pacific Northwest,
salmon is very popular.
And the salmon gravlax
on the homemade rye
is a beautiful dish.
Really fresh, high quality.
It is unique.
All right, so, what
are we making first?
We're gonna start out
with our rye bread.
We mill our whole grains
here on site.
Of course we do.
This is
a Turkey Red wheat.
It's an heirloom grain.
Okay.
Switch on this little
knob here.
[ Machine whirring, grinding ]
Wow!
Look at that, huh?
This is another rye berry
that's grown just down the road.
[ Whirring, grinding continue ]
So, this is the Turkey Red wheat
and then the rye, water.
And the starter?
Yep.
So, this is natural yeast?
Yeah.
You do this about 8 to 12 hours
before you mix your final dough.
Then mix it
with more flour...
Salt...
...a little more yeast.
...water,
about an hour bulk ferment,
and then they're gonna rest,
and then we're gonna do
a final shape on them.
Rye not?
Proof, into the oven.
It goes for about 30 minutes.
We start it at 500 and then
drop it to about 475 to finish.
You know what I have
to say about that?
Rye-t on.
[Right]
[ Chuckles ]
Rye-t on! Ha!
This is our gravlax.
We've got this nice
sockeye salmon here.
We're just gonna put
a little oil down.
Hit it with some
lemon zest.
Zest is the best.
Oh, yeah, totally.
And then we've got some dill.
Beets go down next.
We got our dry rub --
so, this is brown sugar,
white sugar, salt,
powdered horseradish.
I like it.
Hit it with your dry rub.
And how long
is this gravlax gonna take?
About 36 to 48 hours.
Rinse it off?
Smoke it.
Hickory?
Yep.
Stove top, not necessarily
a lot of heat.
It'll stay primarily as a raw,
cold-smoked salmon.
Exactly.
Let's get it together.
Let's do it.
Rye bread.
[ Moans ]
So, we're gonna get these
toasting off.
Just a little balsamic.
This is a pesto aioli.
Got it.
We got our salmon here.
You can see that beet really
just infused in there.
Thinly sliced beet, radish,
pickled onions,
a little crème fraîche...
Beautiful.
...fried capers because you need
a little crispy on there,
and dill.
Hi, welcome to Norway.
I'm Sven.
This is delicious.
You want to slow down
when you eat it
to really appreciate the depth
of what went on here
'cause it's exactly
my mom's set up.
It has a really nice,
refined Scandinavian feel to it.
It tastes even better
than it looks,
and that's quite
a picture right there.
Mmm.
Love this.
Nicely done.
Got two salmon gravlax
going out!
The rye bread is delicious,
and the salmon pairs
well with the other ingredients.
You still got that
veg tartine working, too?
COOK:
Going down right now.
Love coming here,
supporting the local community.
It's so cozy and homelike.
I like that they put
the glass windows here.
Do you come here
for the stadium show?
It's wonderful --
the smell.
Crazy.
And on top of the whole thing,
it's all fresh.
You can get fresh bread
from a drive-through.
They've got all of your dining
needs covered for the whole day.
So, now we're gonna
change gears, though...
Yep.
...from the artisan style
to the indulgent.
An Ethos burger
with sweet potato chips.
FIERI:
You've got to see this!
This burger is incredible.
Coming up next...
That is one of the most
outside-of-the-box burgers
I've ever had
on "Triple D."
Gingerbread?
Yep, you got it.
Gingerbread
or a ninja star?
You be the judge.
[ Beep ]
FIERI:
"Triple D" is scratch-baking...
Can I get some buns
from the bakery, please?
...and homemaking...
Two stuffed mushrooms,
two gravlax salmon.
...at Ethos Bakery & Café
in Richland, Washington.
Ethos does elevated,
amazing food.
Perfect for breakfast,
lunch, dinner.
Got an Ethos burger going out.
I have trouble ordering anything
else but the Ethos burger.
It has this super buttery,
flaky croissant bun.
MAN: The bacon topping
with the braised leeks
just takes it
to the next level.
What's the game plan?
This is our croissant.
So, get your milk going
and the yeast in there,
sugar and salt, and then
we'll pour that into the bowl.
Put your flour in...
Got it.
...butter.
And then the starter?
That's right.
So, this gets mixed up
for how long?
Probably 10 minutes.
Let it rest, and then we're
gonna get ready to laminate.
Here we go.
Butter is just gonna go
right in the middle like that.
Sheet it out.
[ Mechanical whirring,
clicking ]
I'd sit here and play
with this all day.
And then we do tri-folds.
So this is one, so we're
gonna do it two more times.
And then --
Into the fridge, rest.
Yes.
I'm gonna roll it
out here.
It is just layers of magic.
Our buns are
2 inches by 12 inches rolled up.
You let that proof,
bake it off.
Then they're ready to go
for service.
You are busy people.
All right, next step --
the bacon vinaigrette...
Yes.
...that's going on
top of the burger.
Correct.
We've just got some oil in
there, and you got your bacon,
and that's just gonna get
rendered down.
So, then we're gonna get
the base going on the dressing.
Some brown sugar in here,
maple syrup,
apple cider vinegar,
salt and pepper,
and then you got
your bacon fat.
Now, that's what
I'm talking about.
Oh, yeah.
And then you got
rosemary in there,
and then the crispy bacon
right in there at the end.
Uh-huh!
Bring it.
We got our
nice 8-ounce burger.
Good amount
of salt and pepper.
You're gonna mark it
on the grill
and then finish it
in the oven?
Throw some aromatics --
rosemary, thyme,
and then butter --
and then it goes on
in the oven.
Sit there
and baste in it.
That's right.
It gets hit
with white cheddar.
It's gonna kill me.
You know that.
And this is
our monster --
Croissant bun.
See that nice layers
right there.
Wow!
Crazy.
Mark them off a little bit,
and then you want to get
your bacon vin going.
Get some leeks in there,
as well.
We sauté these with white wine,
salt and pepper.
We got our croissant bun that's
been all toasted off, right?
Sweet potato chips.
Burger down.
Some ooey-gooey goodness
right on top.
There you go --
Ethos burger.
♪♪
That's a real croissant.
I mean, that's, like,
textbook.
You are taking this delicious,
angelic pastry
and hitting it
with a burger.
You're putting monster-truck
tires on a Bentley.
[ Laughs ]
And I would take that
to the county fairgrounds
for race night
any day of the week.
[ Chuckling ]
Wow!
That is one of the most
outside-of-the-box burgers
I've ever had
on "Triple D."
I've had hundreds.
[ Laughs ]
The croissant
holds together.
It soaks it up.
The burger's
cooked perfectly.
The white cheddar
was the perfect kiss.
But it's this leek- and
bacon-vinaigrette jam fest
that you put on there.
Oh, my God!
Amazing.
Awesome.
Wow.
We got three Ethos burgers
all day.
It's a wonderful combination
of flavors.
It's literally a bite of heaven.
Got that shrimp and grits.
I don't know of a place
like this.
You get to have food
from your community.
We really enjoy it.
It's delicious.
Your enthusiasm is contagious.
Your attention to detail coming
from your engineer background,
I now understand it.
And that right there
is really
one of the most
remarkable burgers
I've had in "Triple D."
Good job.
Thank you.
"Engineer," yeah, right.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up...
A place in Vancouver, Canada...
I thought that was the crown
of the pie princess.
...going from meat...
All cheeseburger, all day.
...to sweet.
That's like calling
the space shuttle an airplane.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Vancouver, Canada.
Now, on "Triple D,"
we have fulfilled
the menu
of all of your favorites.
Oh, we've given you pizza,
we've given you burgers,
given you hot dogs,
given you burritos.
We've given you Chinese food,
Mexican food, Italian food.
Oh, we've given you comfort food
and ethnic food.
I mean,
we have really done our job,
but then you write in, and you
say, "You know what, Guy?
You know what we want? Pies."
That's a pie-in-the-sky idea.
This is The Pie Hole.
♪♪
I've got
your chunky-monkey slice.
The food is delicious.
What do you recommend?
Oh, my gosh.
What's my mood today?
I just want one of everything.
FIERI: And thanks to owner
Jenell Parsons' creative mind,
there's more than 100 pies
to choose from.
I've got a 3-D
computer animation degree.
I'm an artist,
so for me, pie is art.
And her master works
are both sweet and savory.
Two bacon-cheeseburger
hand pies.
She put everything great about
a bacon cheeseburger into a pie.
I'd honestly prefer it over
a bacon cheeseburger.
It's great.
The basis of a great pie
is the...?
Crust.
All right,
let's see it.
So, what we start with
is all-purpose flour, sugar,
salt, unsalted cold butter,
and that's, like,
the tip to making
the flaky, buttery layers.
Never in my life seen that
much butter-to-flour ratio.
You've got an issue.
And that ish delicious.
I bet it is.
[ Laughs ]
Water. Keep that
as ice-cold as possible.
Vinegar.
Why the acid?
The acid's gonna help
break down the gluten,
and that's gonna help
give you the flaky layers.
Now we're gonna make
the filling
for the bacon cheeseburger.
Got it.
Ground beef.
Brown the meat up.
Add in the flour,
then milk.
We're gonna build a roux
out of the fat?
Kind of gonna build a roux
out of the fat
right into the pot here.
A little mustard.
Got to have
the American cheese.
And then the pickles
give you a little bit of bite.
So, you're gonna have
the reminiscent flavors
that everybody expects.
You bet.
And then
last but not least --
a little salt, pepper,
and...?
A little bit
of white pepper.
Living on the edge.
Yep.
We're gonna roll this now
that it's rested.
We have a trusty
little ring.
I thought that was the crown
of the pie princess.
Well, it could be.
We're gonna put a little bit
of our egg wash.
This is gonna act
like the glue,
and we've got our filling
that's now been cooled.
Two scoops, so it's like
a double patty.
Then we're gonna add
some cheese, bacon,
onions, mustard,
and then we got
to close these up.
Good luck with that.
So, that's
the Super Crimper 9000?
The egg wash is what gives
you that gorgeous color.
The sheen.
Steam has to escape.
A little sesame seed.
Oh, I like this.
FIERI: What temp?
How long?
PARSONS: 350,
about 35, 40 minutes.
♪♪
It's delicious.
It tastes just like
a cheeseburger.
The pie crust --
flaky is an understatement.
Do not eat this
in black.
All cheeseburger,
all day.
I mean, there's no question
why that's such a hit.
Good portions, nice
presentation, and very mindful.
Thank you.
MAN: So, as soon as you bite in,
you get the meaty taste
but then also the pickles
and the mustard.
Perfection.
I can make pie crust,
but I can't make
pie crust like this.
Not this good.
I mean, this is --
There's something going on here.
There's something.
WOMAN:
The place is just so fun
and just makes you feel
really comfortable as soon
as you walk in the door.
You have a neon that says,
"Stuff your pie hole."
Yes.
Probably the coolest sign
I've ever seen in my life.
I'm not kidding you.
Out of the 1,100-plus "Triple D"
joints we've ever done,
"The Pie Hole,"
best name ever.
FIERI: And one of Jenell's best
pies is the one
she says customers
are obsessed with.
Got a raspberry cream
crumble sliced up.
It's sweet.
It's tart.
It's perfect.
We're gonna make the custard
for the raspberry cream pie.
Start with some eggs.
I mean, I don't like eggs,
but if they look like that --
They're organic. They're local.
They're free-run.
They're the happiest
chickens you can find.
We're gonna add some
sour cream, sugar,
some flour,
vanilla, and some salt.
Got it.
Okay.
Next.
We're gonna make
the crumble next.
We've got butter,
flour, and sugar.
Break it down
into the gravel.
Same crust.
And I just use the pie plate
as my template.
Look how thick
that crust is.
And now is doing
the beautiful edge.
Do you want to do it?
Oh, yeah, no.
[ Laughs ]
It's gorgeous,
by the way.
My term for this
is forking.
Okay, but you dock it.
But you dock it.
Good berries.
Nice, eh?
Mmm.
Don't you know.
That's how many goes
in this?
Yeah.
We've got our custard.
Holy moly.
I thought there was gonna be
some raspberries.
I didn't think there were gonna
be 8,000 raspberries.
You can't call it
a raspberry cream pie
if you don't fill it
right up, right?
Yeah, don't you know?
And then this beautiful
buttery crumble.
All right.
We bake them on a tray
because the raspberries
are gonna burst.
If a pie is not oozing
over the edge, it's not a pie.
Because this one is so big,
we're gonna be putting this
in the oven
for almost two hours.
Really? 350?
We're out.
We're cooled.
Get our big old knife.
What's that method
right there?
This method?
It's the stabby method.
Eeh, eeh, eeh!
[ Laughs ]
There you go.
♪♪
That is so far past
what I think
the average person
would call a berry pie.
That's like calling
the space shuttle an airplane.
That's a whole different
level of pie.
The crust is as tender
and as crunchy
and as moist
as a butter cookie.
But the cream with the eggs
and the sugar and the flour
and the sour cream
with that little bit of tang...
Yeah.
...and then all those fresh
berries that have cooked down --
I mean, you made the jam
right inside of the pie. Wow.
Not only does it change
my expectation of berry pies,
it changed my expectation
for pies in general.
That really embarrasses
a lot of pies.
PARSONS:
Raspberry cream crumble.
It's creamy.
It's got the tartness
of raspberries.
The crumble on the top
is my favorite part.
It'll ruin you forever.
It will ruin you forever.
You going sweet
or savory?
Every time I step in, it's just
like walking into heaven.
From having
100-plus recipes
and what people get
in the experience,
I don't know
where your ceiling is.
Oh, goose bumps.
Well done.
Thank you.
So, was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
When a job makes you cry,
you walk out
because life is too short
to be miserable, and --
[ Crying ]
I got to go!
Don't.
No, come back.
Come back. Come back.
I can't do it anymore.
Just kidding.
[ Laughter ]