You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out, it was only
the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
[ Engine revs ]
Like on this trip.
This is outrageous.
I'm heading back to some of
my old stomping grounds
in my hometown
of Santa Rosa.
Shake your booty.
[ Laughs ]
Real deal Mexican...
This is dynamite.
I started to drool a little bit.
...the whole Fieri family
is a fan of.
How is it, Mom?
Delicious.
A pizza joint
in Eureka, California...
That's gangster.
...serving slices straight
out of Jersey.
[ Imitating accent ]
One, two, three.
Three pizza ovens.
Three, all day.
[ Chuckles ]
And in Las Vegas...
I want the stromboli recipe.
[ Laughs ]
Well...
...I'm hitting up
an old college hangout
where the 'bolis
are still outta bounds.
Dude, that is so money.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
You know, we have traveled
a lot of miles
and a lot of years
on "Triple D,"
and I'm here to take you
to a place that, well,
it was one of the first places
we ever featured Hunter.
Here in our hometown
of Santa Rosa, California,
Hunter and I have been rolling
to this place for years.
And I learned what
everybody learns
when you see your favorite
joint make it on "Triple D,"
you learn to wait in line.
This is La Texanita.
♪♪
Finding authentic Mexican food,
I mean, this is definitely
the place to go.
FIERI: That's all thanks
to Alma Mendez,
my sister from another mister.
We both get our hair done
by the same guy.
[ Laughs ]
That's funny.
Or at least she used to be.
This can't be the real you.
-Where's your hair?
-I just changed my hair.
I've never seen your hair
that color.
[ Laughs ]
Now, her looks might have
changed,
but the food, that's still as
legit Mexican as you can find.
I tell you that this is one
of my favorite places,
but when your mom
and dad are here,
then you know
it's the real deal.
How is it, Mom?
I love all their food here.
Dad, in terms of the posole...
Just like in Colima.
It's as real as it gets?
Real as it gets.
The posole.
When I am home off the road
from "Triple D,"
definitely one of my stops
is coming by to get this.
FIERI: What are we gonna
start off with?
Boiling water, onions.
And the whole garlic?
Yes.
Add the salt.
Now we have to add pork meat.
-Pigs' feet?
-Pigs' feet.
This is interesting.
I didn't know there was
pigs' feet in posole.
You're number one.
-How long is this gonna cook?
-For an hour.
Now we have to add the posole.
This is corn.
It's been soaked.
Yes.
Some chicken base.
And here's the Guajillo.
The Guajillo sauce.
This is the Guajillo chile.
We took the stems off,
took the seeds out,
let them sit there and steep,
blended them,
put a little bit of water, then
ran it through the strainer.
Makes this really nice
almost like enchilada sauce,
and this is kind of really
the flavor base of this.
Yeah, this is gonna be
sitting here for 20 minutes.
Then, ready to serve.
This is...
The back bone,
and there's some feet.
Look at that color
in the hominy.
I'm sorry.
I started to drool a little bit.
♪♪
[ Crunches ] Mm.
This is about as "real deal"
as you can get.
The hominy has nice texture.
It's fantastic.
The broth is really nice
and light.
Adding things like
the pigs' feet,
you just get real flavors
in there.
I have got to admit --
I dig the hoof.
♪♪
Is there posole all the time now
or just on the weekends?
Only Friday, Saturday,
and Sunday.
You've gotta get posole
all the time.
You're killing me.
It's my favorite thing
in the world.
But this piping hot molcajete
might run a close second.
How long have you been
doing molcajetes?
We had a special when we did
the "Triple D" show,
but now we're making it
every single day.
We're gonna make
our chimichurri,
the one that we used to marinate
our chicken
and beef
for the molcajetes.
Salt, garlic, parsley,
basil, olive oil,
and then we're gonna blend it.
[ Whirs ]
♪♪
Now we're gonna marinate
the shrimp.
We add some chopped garlic
with olive oil
and Worcestershire,
and we mix it all together.
We're gonna make
our salsa molcajete.
Add the salt, garlic,
some chilies.
They're already toasted.
And tomatoes.
We add some water,
and it's ready to blend.
We're gonna add the molcajete
sauce and some boiled cactus,
and we just let it sit.
Now we're gonna have our stone,
our molcajete, to heat up.
While this is getting ready,
we're gonna make our meats.
We've got panela cheese
and the green onions.
Now we're ready to assemble.
[ Sizzling ]
♪♪
This is outrageous.
This is really hot.
They're becoming
quite the thing now.
Everybody likes the molcajete.
This is dynamite.
Nice little spice to this.
Not too hot.
A lot of flavor, very juicy.
♪♪
Hi, lady.
Molcajete meats.
The beef was very delicious,
marinated, and spicy.
There's some tomato base to it,
and it's just really delicious.
And it's one of my favorites.
Still making handmade tortillas?
Still.
Okay.
With a Terminator
tortilla maker.
♪♪
Where did this come from?
It's from Mexico.
I've never seen this one.
This is like the Terminator
of tortilla makers.
Do you know that someone's
probably gonna steal this today?
-No.
-Yeah.
FIERI: Fortunately,
someone didn't have to.
ALMA:
I gave him one as a present.
One time, I bring one from
Mexico, and he was so happy.
This starts with adding the
masa, and this is dried corn?
Yeah, use water here.
This is the hard part,
getting the masa ready.
So we want it to be
just a little bit tacky.
Yeah.
Put it in a nice, firm ball
so it doesn't dry out.
That's one big tortilla.
Yeah.
Now, do you patty yours a little
bit before you put it down?
Yeah.
You have to go like this.
And you gotta make that noise
when you're doing tortillas.
Oh, you do?
Yeah.
Watch this. How about this?
I could always go like this...
[ Tapping foot ]
See?
It's not same.
And press, and this
is the tortilla.
And then we go, and we lay it
on the tortilla
till they're nice and brown,
and they're ready to go.
Yes.
♪♪
What do people order the most
when they come in?
Tacos carne asada.
The famous carne asada
at La Texanita?
Yes, that one.
FIERI:
And when we come back...
I'm getting
a La Texanita 101 right here.
After years of begging...
I've been asking
for this recipe
since I've been coming here
for the last five years.
...fingers crossed that
I finally learn the secret.
Better not be super simple.
And the whole family's
trying to get in on the action.
It's my nephew calling, wanting
me to bring him some food.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Back in 2009,
I introduced the nation
to a joint
in my hometown
of Santa Rosa --
a place the whole family hits up
whenever I'm back
from a "Triple D" road trip.
Now, we've got all kinds of
great Mexican restaurants
up and down this street.
But for some reason,
between the story,
the people,
and the great food,
La Texanita has become
one of our favorites.
♪♪
And over the last ten years,
nothing's changed.
Everybody knows that I'm here,
so as soon as they --
It's Jules calling.
It's my nephew calling, wanting
me to bring him some food.
[ Laughs ]
And one this we're always
jonesing for --
The famous carne asada
at La Texanita.
Yes, that one.
You guys don't even know
how lucky you are.
I've been asking
for this recipe
since I've been coming here
for the last five years.
And I said, "No, I'm not gonna
give it to you,"
but you know,
we were on the show,
and I had to tell him
my secret.
-[ Laughs ]
-I'm glad you're here.
Better not be super simple
because I've never been able
to figure it out.
It's really simple.
Ah!
We have some chopped onions.
Cook a little bit
the onion here.
Like you're air drumming.
When we hear this noise,
that means that we're cooking.
Put the meat on it,
and then we add the salt.
When you're chopping,
you have to shake your booty.
That's part of cooking it?
Yeah. Yeah.
See, that's why it doesn't
taste the same at my house.
See?
A lot of customers,
when they see that episode,
they say,
"Can you shake your booty?"
Shake your booty.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
When it's almost ready, we add
some lime juice, and we're done.
Here's the tortillas.
Cook 'em up till
they're nice and brown.
So now we're ready
to make our taco.
We have to put some onions,
cilantro, and some salsa.
We add radishes, lime,
and some jalapeños,
and they're ready to go.
Look at that setup.
Oh, so simple...
but so good.
Onions almost have
their own sweetness to 'em,
and the natural juices
and the fat from the meat
cooked everything,
but I'm telling you something.
There's just nothing that can
beat the handmade tortilla.
Mm.
FIERI: Except for maybe
the handmade sope.
They look like corn tortilla
tart shells.
They got a little dip
in 'em like this.
My buddy, Cesar,
taught me how to make 'em.
I want to see how you do 'em,
make sure
Cesar taught me
the right way.
We're gonna grab a big piece
of masa like that, right?
Yeah, you go like this.
You didn't make the noise.
Yes, we do need
the tortilla press for this.
I don't need it.
Oh, you don't use it?
[ Whimsical music plays ]
[ Laughs ]
They're ready.
Throw 'em on the griddle,
brown 'em on both sides,
and then we throw 'em
in the fryer.
Actually, we have to dip it
on the salsa.
We dip it in the salsa
and then in the fryer.
Yes.
That's why hers are so much
better than mine.
-Ah!
-[ Laughs ]
I need those ones.
Where they are?
[ Laughs ]
Could be a routine.
We could...
Now we have to add
the picadillo.
Potatoes, pork, beef, carrots,
the zucchini, a little cumino.
Sope de picadillo.
Put lettuce on it,
Mexican cheese.
And then this -- this is
the key right here. Watch.
[ Drum roll ]
The special sauce,
this is the key.
That is the key.
Yeah.
And this is such a big flavor
because of the size
of that sope.
I mean, two of these,
and I'm done.
You pick up some of
the pepper flavor,
sweetness of the carrots.
And the salsa on top makes it.
♪♪
Whoo-whoo.
[ Laughs ]
Hands down,
one of my favorites.
♪♪
What's the new sope?
Carnitas sope.
We're gonna mix
all these ingredients
to add it
to our carnitas.
Salt, oregano, garlic,
chopped onions,
and milk
to make the meat soft.
[ Whirring ]
Now we're ready to make
our carnitas.
When the pork is cooked
a little bit,
we add onion and milk mix.
Add the bay leaf.
Now we're ready
to assemble our sope.
Refried beans, the carnitas,
lettuce, Mexican cheese,
and our sauce.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
♪♪
The sope is great.
You get a little bit
of crunch on the outside.
Nice and soft and tender
on the inside.
The cheese, a little bit salty
like a Parmesan.
This is excellent.
I'll say it's a little
on the milder side,
not exactly spicy-spicy,
but it's got
the right texture to it.
You get the crunch
from the bottom tortilla,
mixed on top with the pork.
It's absolutely phenomenal.
When you shoot "Triple D"
in your hometown,
this is one of
the first places
that I really had to feel
what everybody else felt.
'Cause I remember coming here
after the show aired,
driving up, and seeing
30 people standing in line.
I'm glad things are still
going so good.
You call me when
it's posole every day.
That's all I want
is posole every day.
♪♪
I mean, is that too much
to ask for, posole every day?
I'm just gonna keep asking
until it becomes a reality.
Now coming up...
What the --
...Jersey meets Cali.
How dead are you with all
your boys on the East Coast
when they find out
you got pineapple?
[ Laughs ]
And it's a match
made in heaven.
Out of bounds, man.
♪♪
Back in 2013, I met this dude
who was putting
Eureka, California, on the map
with his real-deal
New York-style pie.
And thankfully, he hasn't
stopped slinging the dough.
This is Paul's
Live From New York.
♪♪
-Here's your King Kong.
-Nice.
The crust is pretty authentic
New York.
You can take it.
You can fold it.
Isn't that beautiful?
We like the idea of being able
to try different slices
instead of getting
a whole pizza.
FIERI:
That "pizza by the slice" idea
brought here by this guy,
Paul Amato,
all the way from Jersey.
So when you came out here,
you couldn't find a place
that did slices.
No.
No, nothing.
Or even this style of pizza.
No.
PAUL:
When you're making hand-tossed
pizza in Northern California,
you don't find a lot of people
that know how to do that.
Back East in Jersey,
there's a dime a dozen.
It is legit, man,
I'm telling you something.
Thank you.
There is no doubt
that this is the true
New York-style pizzeria.
[ Imitating New York accent ]
One, two, three.
Three pizza ovens.
Three, all day.
Three of 'em.
What do you got?
What are we gonna have?
The margherita.
Whoa!
This is going to define
a lot right here.
I just want you to watch this,
and we're gonna see.
Here we go.
[ Bouncy music ]
What the -- are you doing?
Chunks and splatters.
He was ready for me
to do the spiral,
but I was making
a margherita.
I'm outta here.
[ Laughs ]
Mozzarella chunks.
I can't watch any of this.
In we go. Beautiful.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
Yeah.
See, I like how the chunks
melted.
A little basil.
And a little romano.
Look at that.
Oh! And that fresh basil
right on top,
the little saltiness
of that pecorino romano
coming over the top.
Dude!
Out of bounds, man.
This is, without question,
in the top-five best
margherita pizzas I've ever had.
That's all I needed to hear.
Top five is great for me.
How many different ingredients
do you have for your pies?
Probably 24, maybe more.
How dead are you with all
your boys on the East Coast
when they find out
you got pineapple, huh?
[ Laughs ]
I'm getting abuse
from it already.
We come up with new stuff
all the time.
FIERI: That includes this beast,
the King Kong.
♪♪
It has six meats on it,
pepperoni, the sausage, bacon,
Canadian bacon, some salami,
and our in-house-made meatballs.
Now we're ready to go
in the oven.
King Kong up.
The King Kong pizza
is a perfect meat-lovers pizza.
It's a little spicy with
the meatballs and the pepperoni
and the Canadian bacon,
but it's delicious.
It's very easy to eat too much.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: And here, the pie's
not always round.
Now, what is a Sicilian?
It's a square pan.
We making focaccia?
No.
Don't make me eat focaccia
with pizza toppings.
No focaccia.
Nope. Nope.
Sicilian all the way.
I'm Sicilian, and that's
what I was taught,
but he kept on insisting
that it was focaccia.
So, in with the focaccia.
All right.
I says, "No, no, it's definitely
not focaccia, you know."
This is made by Sicilians
who know.
Look at that.
That's crazy.
Dude.
[ Crunches ]
It is so crispy, so crunchy.
That's legit.
Thank you, that's awesome.
-You kill it, man.
-Thanks, bro.
I want one in Santa Rosa.
I want one in Fortuna.
FIERI: What do they say?
Be careful what you wish for.
PAUL:
We plan to be in Fortuna
in about four months,
rocking and rolling.
That's gangster.
Thanks, man.
[ Whistles ] I get that to go?
You got it.
Okay.
Get a box.
[ Laughs ]
Spreading the slices
all over Northern California,
that's what I like to see,
my friend.
Now I'm headed
to my college town,
Las Vegas, and memories of an
old hangout are flooding back...
Do you know what
we would have given
to get a viewing
of the inner sanctum?
...with the holy moly
stromboli.
It's like something
I've never had before.
♪♪
When "Triple D" was first
gearing up back in 2007...
[ Laughing ]
...I hit up some of
my favorite places
I couldn't wait to share
with the nation.
And this one in Vegas,
well, this was no exception.
In my college days,
we would hang out here
for cold beer
and killer strombolis,
and well, 30-plus years later,
it's still killing it.
This is Four Kegs Sports Pub.
♪♪
Large original 'boli, hot wings.
Their stromboli was definitely
what kicked off the original
"Triple D" thing, for sure.
Guy is 100% correct.
Best stromboli ever.
You know what we would have
given back in the day
to get a viewing of the inner
sanctum of the Four Kegs?
And the man still holding
the key,
that's Mario Perkins,
who's been here since 1977.
♪♪
Guy loved the place,
and it's the first place
he thought of when they
come up with the show.
FIERI:
And his 'bolis are the bomb.
That is so money.
I want the stromboli recipe.
[ Laughs ]
Well...we'll give you 80%.
-80%?
-80% is good.
Yep, 80%, that's all he got.
That's all that anybody
will ever get.
The dough that you do, it's like
something I've never had before.
Here's the ingredients,
which you don't know how much.
That's all right, though,
because the camera
will scale it in,
and then I'll be able to --
Not if they can't see it.
Gonna add the yeast,
sugar, salt.
Okay.
Then we just add
this in slowly.
Now, wait a second, here.
This is the form
of measurement?
Did anybody pre-measure this?
Yeah? Yeah.
This is the right amount.
No one even answered you.
Well, I -- So?
I --
It's a regular day.
Oh, my --
[ Both laugh ]
FIERI: Then that dough goes
into pans that,
I think, are older than me.
These pans have been here
as long as I've been here.
The longer they go,
the more they're flavored,
we'll call them.
That's many years
of cooking in there.
I'm gonna make one and then
you're gonna make one.
Oh, so you're really gonna
put me under the pressure.
Mozzarella cheese
right across.
You just want to put the sauce
right across the middle.
Nice ham coverage.
But what happens over here?
You're over.
That's because
you're talking to me.
Oh, okay.
Fold it over like that.
Mush it.
That's the magic.
All right. My turn?
♪♪
Beautiful.
Looks more like a knish,
but that's okay.
He crumpled the edges
to make it all fancy.
How'd I do?
You might get your own show
some day.
Well, you know,
I'm working up.
-Ooh.
-Look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
Which one's better?
The one on the left, I think.
I was one of the judges
for the stromboli.
Your left or our left?
My left.
His looked nice,
but Mario's won.
I whupped his butt, naturally.
Dude.
That is so money.
Strombolis are still king.
Order up, large original 'boli.
FIERI: But they're not
the only thing served
between the dough these days.
MARIO: Well, the Redneck Burger,
it's unique.
I don't think anyone
has anything quite like it.
I believe Johnny come up
with it one day.
Now, Johnny, how long
you been working here?
Since I was 7 years old.
Mario used to babysit me.
FIERI:
Now he's the head chef.
We start with an 8-ounce
Angus beef burger,
then we put the mushrooms,
onions, and jalapeños.
Just a touch of butter, cheese.
One on the buns,
one on the meat.
You can never get enough cheese.
Redneck Burger.
WOMAN: Redneck Burger has
so many vegetables on it,
which I usually do not eat.
Really cheesy, and it's messy.
They're absolutely amazing.
FIERI: But you can't call
yourself a sports bar
unless you've got
some signature wings.
We're gonna start
with the flamer sauce.
It's our house hot sauce.
About that much because
we like them nice and saucy,
and then we mix it
with this habanero hot sauce.
It's a very, very hot,
fruity flavor.
We just roll 'em.
♪♪
Hot wings.
The flaming hot wings
are very hot.
They're hot enough
to power a city.
Super hot, light your mouth
on fire.
FIERI: And if you can't
take the heat...
Scampi sauce, we just start off
with butter,
dried parsley flakes, garlic,
and Parmesan cheese.
When the wings get in there,
it'll melt that butter
nice and liquidy.
Coats the wings real well.
Order up, scampi wings.
The scampi wings
are buttery deliciousness.
You're not gonna find
anything like this.
Mario just asked me if I would
make a little side appetizer.
Guy made his own
sweet hot sauce.
I'm sautéing jalapeños
and some white onions, garlic.
Now I'm gonna throw in
some cherries.
Sweet chili sauce,
little bit of soy,
a little Tabasco.
You have a name for that?
Called 80% Mario.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
That is outstanding, so many
different flavors in one.
Never made our menu,
but it was good.
FIERI: Well, I gotta tell ya,
no matter how you do it,
the best stromboli
I've ever had,
hands down,
Four Kegs Las Vegas.
Thank you very much.
♪♪
Guy, if you want a rematch
on that stromboli,
any time, my place,
you just make the date.
♪♪
You hear that?
A stromboli showdown.
Next time I'm in Vegas,
it's game on, my brother.
But come on.
We all know Mario will always be
the master of his domain.
Just like Alma in Santa Rosa,
whose posole calls my name
every time I'm home.
And Paul in Eureka,
whose New York pie
is like a bite
of the Big Apple.
But those, ladies and gentlemen,
aren't the only ones.
We'll check out more "Diners,
Drive-ins, and Dives"
next time on
"Triple D Nation."
Give me a "time elapsed"
thing on this
where I just sit here
for five minutes,
and then show a temperature
gauge dropping down.
Start here with surface
of the sun,
down here to palatable.