Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive‐ins, and dives.
This trip...
What's that over there?
These are delicious.
It's buns, beef,
and one funky burger.
I want my mommy.
We've got a charcuterie
smorgasbord in Denver.
I want to tour
the showroom.
I want to test drive
everything.
A worldwide web of flavor
in Utah.
That is good.
And in Juneau, Alaska...
You're rocking it,
Bro.
...a chef taking a "bao"...
Benny's with
the bun police.
He doesn't carry a gun,
just a bun.
...in a tiny little trailer.
I mean, Brother,
this is outstanding.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive‐ins
&amp; Dives."
♪♪♪
I'm here in Juneau, Alaska,
right across the street
from where all the big cruise
ships come in,
and great news, folks,
I have got a special guest.
No, it's not an actress,
it's not a sports star,
it's not a politician.
No, it's somebody that's really
big here in Alaska,
and no, it's not Sasquatch.
No, this guy's
from North Pole, Alaska.
He's the triple D‐O‐G.
He's the one and only
Benny Lin from Pagoda.
All right, Chef,
do you like bao buns?
Yes, I do. You want me
to make you some?
I can make you some.
No, Benny,
we've already done that.
You've been on the show.
You're a guest this time.
We're going to go check out
a dude that's making great buns.
This is Bun Daddy.
Full Boar coming up next.
Bun Daddy has a unique flavor
in Juneau.
I would describe it as a street
taco mated with a steamed bun,
and they created some magic.
FIERI:
All conjured up in a 1968 camper
by husband and wife team,
Laura Steele
and Max Goldrich.
Where did you learn
to cook? Just...
Self‐taught.
I loved steam buns
and I couldn't get the ones here
that I wanted to eat.
It ain't no fun
unless you got buns, hun?
Exactly.
The buns are really fluffy
and delicious.
Almost like a cotton
candy of bread.
We got a Belly of the Beast
bun coming up.
Belly of the Beast is kinda like
a bacon lover's dream.
A little bit of veg on there,
the sriracha sauce.
Unicorn pork buns.
So, let's make
the buns.
GOLDRICH:
We're going to start out
with the water here,
we've got sugar next,
and then we'll add the yeast,
oil, baking powder,
and all‐purpose flour.
‐No eggs, huh?
‐No.
Make notes.
So you make all these buns
in this little trailer?
By scratch every day.
Cruise ships run
May to September.
That's when we're open.
‐What do you do after that?
Go to the Legislature
and work there for a little bit.
Go from Buns
to Legislature?
‐Yeah.
‐All right, after it's done?
Proof for about an hour
or so until it doubles.
Portion that.
‐How many ounces?
‐2 ounces.
‐Pretty spot‐on.
And I roll them.
So, you're turning
it inside to itself?
Yeah. Let those
proof again,
roll it out,
do a drop of oil on it.
Fold it in half.
Throw it in on the steamer.
‐How long is it go?
‐10 to 12 minutes.
Really impressed.
Benny's with the bun police.
Benny is a bun cop.
He doesn't carry a gun,
just a bun.
FIERI:
Filmed on location with the men
and women of Flavortown.
All right, we're going
to do the pork belly.
For the glaze,
first, we will add the sriracha,
rice vinegar, hoisin, and honey.
‐Oh, that's nice.
Pour some in here.
Seal that up.
Go into the sous‐vide
for seven hours.
176.
Well, I do it at 178.
Benny, what temperature
you do it at?
‐179.
‐Ooh.
‐Yeah, see.
‐Pork belly is done.
I reserve this extra liquid
as a sauce to put on top.
Slice up the pork belly,
hit it with the glaze,
and throw it in the oven
for just a couple minutes.
‐Oh, okay.
‐Let it get all tacky on it.
Tacky not like the outfits
you wore in Vegas last year.
See Benny, watch this.
Wow, that's
got great flavor.
‐I like it.
‐Steamed buns, big fatty.
Cucumber.
Green onion, hit it
with the sauce,
and then a little sprinkling
of sesame seeds.
Here you go Benny.
Let's take a bite.
Wow.
I told him you were
the bun police.
Now, you're going
to steal the recipe?
‐Yeah. [ Laughs ]
‐I think it's dynamite.
The pork belly itself
is spot‐on.
It's not
your typical bun.
♪♪♪
It's a little less
doughy.
The cucumber's a nice touch,
a little sesame seed.
Sell the sauce.
‐Yeah, it's good.
‐You're rocking it, Bro.
I got a Belly of the Beast
for Buck.
The pork belly is ‐‐
just melts in your mouth.
Juicy and full of flavor.
And it goes really good
with the softness of the bun.
‐Can I help the next person?
‐It's delicious.
So, the only thing bad
about Bun Daddy
is that you only get them
in the summer season.
That's right.
MAN: We're a short beat
right next to the ocean.
You definitely get the tourist
people that come out here,
but this is
a local spot, absolutely.
‐Favorite thing on the menu?
‐This chicken is delicious.
He uses a fish sauce marinade.
It's a unique flavor.
It's got fresh jalapeños,
lots of fresh vegetables.
FIERI:
Now we're back in
to make the...
‐Mother Clucker.
Start out with the sugar,
lime juice.
Where's this recipe
come from?
Made it up?
Okay.
Fish sauce?
Yeah, and garlic.
And the bowl. It's part
of the ceremony, Benny.
Boneless, skinless
chicken thighs.
And how long is
that going to marinade?
‐Overnight.
‐And we're going to fry these?
No, we will grill them out
on the barbecue outside.
Okay.
What's up next?
So, we're making pickled
daikon and carrot.
We'll start with rice vinegar,
water, sugar, chili flake.
I like spicy, I just
don't think I've ever had
my pickled daikon and carrots
with that kind of intensity.
I'll put a couple ice cubes
into it.
Just so it's not going to
sit there and cook it.
The daikon and rainbow carrots.
Pour this over the top.
Put it in the refrigerator
to pickle overnight.
Let's see it, Chef.
A little bit of chicken.
Your mouth's watering,
isn't it Benny?
Oh, yeah.
I can hear you making
noises like Mmm, mmm, mmm.
Hoisin sauce,
Japanese Mayo, cucumber ‐‐
He loves
his cucumbers.
‐Jalapeños.
‐Ooh.
Pickled daikon
and carrot.
For a guy that's
not a chef,
you sure have a touch
here, buddy.
Locally grown radish
greens. There you are.
Enjoy, guys.
Can you see me here?
That's my line,
Benny.
Wow, this is good.
The bun, we already know
is dynamite.
The marinade on the chicken's
really dynamite.
The fact that
you're grilling it, home run.
The kicker is that super
unctuous creamy Mayo.
Got a little touch
of sweetness to it.
And then all of a sudden,
the refreshing kick of the acid
from the daikon and the carrot.
‐Yeah.
I mean, Brother,
it's outstanding.
Yep.
Enjoy.
The meat has a little bit
of crispiness on it,
but it's still really juicy.
The spices they put on top,
all the sauces,
it just kind of soaks
right into the bun.
Great combination.
Max finds a way to make
big things happen
in a very small area.
If I was coming to Juneau,
this is where I'd come.
You have great
appreciation for detail.
You're working in
a very confined space.
And what you do
and what you deliver
and how you treat
the public, dude,
you're a reason
to come to Juneau.
Thank you very much.
FIERI: Up next, a carnivore's
dream in Denver...
Keep going before
I eat
everything that goes
on the sandwich.
...artisan cured meats...
Oh, that ham.
...on handcrafted
culinary canvases.
Hi, have you met my friend,
Overachiever?
♪♪♪
So I'm here in the Highlands
area of Denver, Colorado,
and I tell you,
if you ever want
to just parachute
right into an area
and hit some awesome triple D
joints, this would be the place.
Let's see, you've got the second
location for Atomic Cowboy.
You got the second location
for Biju,
Cafe Brazil, you got
Hops &amp; Pie down the street.
And I think we have a new one
to put on the list.
With this chef, he is scratch
making 45 different salumis.
And you know what? He'll even
put it on a sandwich for you.
This is Il Porcellino Salumi.
Andouille sausage.
It's all the delicious meat
you could ever want.
Everything's artisanal.
Everything's made in‐house.
MAN: They're using the same
techniques they did
back in Italy, and in my
opinion, they even do it better.
FIERI: And the man behind
this carnivore emporium
is Bill Miner,
who's all about
making meat his mission.
Been a chef
for the past 20 years.
Found a passion
for cured meats.
Am I at a butcher shop?
A sandwich shop?
Yes.
All of the above.
They have this really
great unique menu
that serves these
incredible sandwiches.
Hoggie sandwich
with an applesauce is up.
I love The Hoggie. That's one
of my favorites.
The soppressata, the capicola,
and then the ham is fantastic.
Great combination of smoke
and spice
that then gets rounded out
by the aioli.
We're making
The Hoggie sandwich.
‐This is your style of ham?
‐This is our style of ham.
What muscle is this
that we have?
So, we could call this
the inside round muscle.
Do we want to call it that or
are we just going to make it up?
‐No, it's called ‐‐
‐Let's call this the...
Let's call it the
inside round.
...the pig one muscle.
No. Make the brine.
Salt, brown sugar,
maple syrup.
Pour some...
Liquid sugar on me?
Some coriander seed, clove,
lot of allspice,
toasted fennel seed,
mustard seed, bay leaf,
celery powder, water.
Bring it up to a boil
and let it simmer
for 5, 7 minutes.
And then once it's cooled
and it's strained,
you can start
the injection?
Absolutely.
You get a little bit
of that liquid in here.
And we'll let this set up
for how long
before we start
to cook it?
10 days.
Tie it...
‐Smoke it.
‐...smoke it on hickory.
Dig it.
All right, Soppressata.
First we have
to mix our spices.
Dextrose, which is
a pine sugar,
Sicilian Sea Salt,
Calabrian Chilies,
and Italian hot pepper,
sweet Calabrian powder,
toasted fennel seed,
garlic powder,
black pepper, celery powder.
‐Got it.
So ground pork shoulder,
add our frozen pork fat to that.
Season this up.
Add some red wine.
Soppressata going into
our sown hog casing.
Tie up the end real quick,
and do lots of loops and knots.
We're going to loop
and knot this for the rest
of the week, Captain,
or we making a quilt?
So in the fermentation
chamber for about 48 hours,
and then into
our drying room,
which sits at about 60 degrees
for about 10 weeks.
Should I just start
eating it now...
Not yet.
...or wait till it
goes on a sandwich?
Not yet.
We've got our Soppressata.
Now what's that
over there?
These are delicious.
Keep going before
I eat everything
that goes
on the sandwich.
I'm going to show you the inside
of this capicola real quick.
What do we rub that in?
Fennel seed, Calabrian Chili,
a little garlic pepper.
Delicious.
Slice this ciabatta
right in half
and get it toasting
on the flat top.
Garlic aioli.
Layer these meats on here,
so we've got our Berkeley Ham.
Layer these meats
in my mouth.
Oh, that ham.
‐It's good, right?
No, this is not good.
There's not even close to good.
Good's here.
This is where your ham is.
Like skyscraper ham.
We've got our capicola, our
Soppressata, pickled peppers.
If you made those,
I'm going to just kick you.
We make
the pickled peppers.
Of course we do,
we make the peppers.
Tomatoes.
We also milled this wood,
and he hand‐carved this.
Baby romaine that are dressed
with a red wine vinaigrette.
♪♪♪
Putting that delicious salumi
inside of the bread,
is kind of like putting
the '68 with a car cover.
You're hiding all the beauty.
Except that bread is spot‐on.
Little acid
from the baby romaine,
the tomatoes,
and the pickled peppers.
That's a definition
of an Italian deli sandwich.
Oh, oh.
Got a Hoggie and applesauce
for you, ma'am.
The ham has a really
great smoke on it.
Capicola
is just amazing.
Brings a little bit
of spice to it.
You're not going to find
a better sandwich in Denver.
Anything else you'd recommend
for a charcuterie platter?
FIERI: You have retail.
People can buy it to‐go.
We do fresh butcher
cuts.
How many different types
of charcuterie?
40, 50.
‐No.
‐For real.
I want to tour the showroom.
I want to test drive everything.
We're going to do
the roast beef sandwich next.
There is a roast beef for you.
Super tender,
super moist meat.
I get a craving for this, and
I'm in my car, on my way here.
Bringing the knuckles.
See you in a minute....
I can't hang out with him
anymore.
I'm going to go to jail.
I'm going to end up being
in trouble in this town.
Welcome back.
Triple D hanging out
at Il Porcellino Salumi.
Huh?
‐Did I get that right?
‐Got it.
Denver, Colorado.
Bill is crushing it.
He makes over
45 different salumis.
House cures, brines,
dry ages, you name it.
On and on...
Way overachiever.
The attention to detail
they put into the meats,
knowing how it's going to come
out in a sandwich is incredible.
I'm trying to get everything
on the menu right now,
but I really love
the roast beef.
Roast beef sandwich is up.
It's a good blend between
the meat and the horseradish
and the melted cheddar.
The arugula gives it
a fresh pop.
The jam is that sweetness that
kind of brings it all together.
So we're going to do
the roast beef sandwich next.
We use inside top round.
We brine it.
Got it.
So salt, fresh thyme, bay leaf,
peppercorns, water.
Bring it up to a boil.
Cool it down.
Then we brine the beef.
And then when we come out,
what's the roast?
We actually sous‐vide it,
so cook it in a hot water bath,
110 degrees
for four hours.
Hi, have you met
my friend Overachiever?
We rub it in beef tallow
and black pepper,
and it's going to go in the oven
for about 20 minutes
at 350 degrees.
What else are we going
to serve on this?
‐Onion jam.
‐Cool.
So, we got a hot pan
with some oil.
Add our onions, a little salt,
a little pepper,
and let them caramelize
for three to four hours.
And get those
into the food processor.
Fresh thyme and a little bit
of that sherry vinegar.
Oh, just a touch?
Turn that on.
A little bit of water.
Into the stove top.
A little bit of water,
apple pectin, sugar,
and we'll let that simmer
and kind of come together.
Simmer down now. All right.
What's on the menu?
‐Apple Cider Gastrique.
‐Okay.
We make our own applesauce
here, too,
so we keep the cores
and the peels from the apples.
Locally made apple cider,
apple cider vinegar,
honey, brown sugar.
Let that simmer
for a few hours.
Strain it out, thicken it with
a little bit of xanthan gum.
Can we finally
have the sandwich?
We can
have the sandwich.
There were four days
we've been here.
Slice our beautiful
baguette
and get this toasting
on the flat top.
Heat up our roast beef.
‐Look at that.
Get a little bit
of our onion jam
on one side,
horseradish,
and we're going to go ahead
and melt the cheese,
and then we add a beef
au jus that we make, right?
Cheese is all melty.
‐Okay.
Fresh baby arugula on there,
salt and pepper,
and our Apple Cider
Gastrique.
Another one of our
overachieving liquids.
And this is our roast
beef sandwich.
♪♪♪
You take
the roast beef
and you baby it with your brine
and your sous‐vide,
and then you cut it so thin,
it's only got one side.
You can use that.
‐I like that.
You hit it with the gastrique,
the onion jam, the horseradish,
and then you top it
with a little fresh
respite of the baby arugula
with the nice little pepper,
nice little crunch.
There's not many roast beefs
I've ever had like that.
I mean, this is so refined
and done with such discipline ‐‐
every aspect, every aspect.
And when you can take something
as simple as a roast beef
and make it an orchestra
of flavor like that,
that's when
you're doing it right.
Awesome.
‐Thank you.
Here is a roast beef for you.
The roast beef is very juicy
and tender.
The Cider Gastrique is
what really does it
over the top for me.
Good sweetness, good savory.
And it's just delicious.
Wook sandwich up.
When you first came here,
and then you told people
about it,
how did you explain what it was?
Just the best sandwich shop
in Denver.
‐Pretty legit, right?
‐Legit.
Don't see many places like this.
Really dynamite.
Thanks for tuning in.
Don't touch it.
[ Laughs ]
I wouldn't dare.
FIERI: Coming up...
We're headed to Utah
for some international flair.
Oh, I'm dying
to try this.
...and enjoy dishing up
a Peruvian classic.
This is not lacking
in flavor one bit.
...and putting peanut butter
on a burger?
Come to Logan, Utah,
and try that burger!
♪♪♪
So, I'm here in Utah.
I love coming to this state.
I mean, we're talking
about great people.
We're talking
about lots to do.
We're talking about
tons of community.
And what does that give you?
It gives you a place
that people,
they love to go out and eat.
So I'm here in Logan, Utah,
about an hour and a half
from Salt Lake city
to check out a restaurant.
Oh, this is awesome.
The chef is from Mexico,
he went to California,
he cooked for President Reagan,
he came out here to Logan.
What's he serving up?
Big flavors.
This is Sabores
international cuisine.
Pad Thai, one minute.
It was a instant hit with me.
All sorts of people
can come here,
and they can all find
something they like.
Torta de Pierna.
The best comfort foods from all
around the world
on one great menu.
FIERI:
Those are flavors Eliseo Garcia
became passionate
about after working in kitchens
all over the West with chefs
from all over the world.
GARCIA:
Sabores is flavor.
So, lots of flavor?
Cuban, Puerto Rico,
Argentina.
I'm thinking, [ Gasps ]
"I'm going to Mexico tonight,"
or, "I'm going to Vietnam."
I can have the Pad Thai
or the Lomo Saltado.
GARCIA:
Lomo Saltado up.
I first had lomo saltado
in Lima, Peru.
This was very true
to how you get it there.
It's beef and onions and fries
with this amazing sauce.
It's really delicious.
‐So, what are we going to make?
Ranchero sauce for
the lomo saltado.
Lomo saltado.
Put some oil, onions, garlic,
tomatoes, Aji Panca.
Not ahi, the tuna.
Aji, the pepper.
Some tomato juice.
Jalapeños.
‐Cilantro.
‐And a little salt and pepper.
And that's it.
Next step, what are we
going to do?
We're going to make
the aji sauce.
Mayonnaise? Aji?
Aji Amarillo, jalapeños,
salt, pepper,
fresh garlic, lemon juice,
cilantro, romaine lettuce.
♪♪♪
All right.
Oh, this is completely
out of my bandwidth.
I've never in the history
seen lettuce mixed into a sauce.
‐Right.
‐Oh, I'm dying to try this.
I get the texture
of the lettuce.
I guess it gives
some of the body to it.
Okay. That is one of the
craziest sauces I've ever seen.
Let's cut some sirloin.
Chef, where did you
learn to cook?
California. I met
President Reagan there
because I made food
for him for three years.
What was his favorite dish
that you used to make him?
Salad, sandwiches, soup.
You never made
him lomo saltado?
‐Nope.
‐You make it for me.
Let's put oil, sirloin,
stir a little bit.
Some bell peppers.
‐Salt, pepper.
Garlic, balsamic.
Caramelize the meat.
Some soy sauce.
The ranchero sauce.
Ready to plate.
Comes with steamed rice,
french fries.
Beautiful.
It's garnished with chopped
parsley with a side of aji.
♪♪♪
This is not lacking
in flavor one bit.
Tender meat, lots of onions
and tomatoes.
Little crunch of the french fry,
little soy sauce.
The ranchero sauce
is the key.
I think our President Reagan
missed out.
I know.
He was having a soup,
salad, and sandwiches?
Excellent.
‐One minute on the lomo saltado.
MAN: The flavors are great.
The rice and the fries
play well together.
‐Really good.
‐Legit.
‐Spring rolls coming out.
The variety is one of the things
I liked best.
Peanut Butter burger up.
The Peanut Butter Burger
is one of my favorites here.
WOMAN: You wouldn't think
the peanut butter
and the burger
would go great together,
but man,
what a combination it is.
The last time I had
a peanut butter burger,
I wanted my mommy.
It was in West Lafayette,
Indiana,
at the Triple XXX
Family Restaurant.
I absolutely don't enjoy
that at all.
I didn't know
how to handle that.
That was the craziest
thing ever,
but I got faith
in my chef here.
Let's make
some chipotle aioli.
Chipotle peppers,
lemon juice, garlic, salt
and pepper, chipotle powder.
You're going to fold that
into the mayonnaise?
That would make
anything taste great.
Let's make some house chips.
Let's start with purple yam.
You're going to go to all
this effort to make the chips?
Yep. Regular yam, potatoes,
Japanese yam.
You're yamming.
Lotus root.
‐Lotus root.
We're going to fry it
for three minutes.
While those are frying,
what do we do?
We're going to make
our house seasoning.
Garlic powder, cumin,
achiote, paprika,
onion powder, salt,
pepper, white pepper.
Season our chips.
They sure make
eclectic chips.
Let's build our peanut
butter burger.
Put the cheese
and the bacon.
Don't overdo it
on the peanut butter.
Chipotle aioli, sriracha sauce.
Lettuce, tomatoes, and onions.
Hamburger,
and there you go, sir.
♪♪♪
I want my mommy...
to come to Logan, Utah,
and try that burger.
♪♪♪
That's good.
That chipotle aioli
and a little bit of the sriracha
take the burger from being sweet
and really heavy peanut butter
to being a little spicy
peanut butter
like a Thai peanut
dipping sauce.
Delicious chips.
I see what everybody liked
about the Peanut Butter Burger.
Maybe it just
took me some time.
Hey, Triple XXX team,
I'll come back.
I'll try the burger again,
all right?
Peanut Butter in two minutes.
It's interesting how
the hamburger works
with the peanut butter.
I love the sweet and the savory.
The chips are good.
I like how crispy they are.
Torta de Pierna up.
WOMAN: You want something hearty
and comforting,
and this is the place to go.
FIERI:
Everybody that comes
here digs it?
It's the jewel of our valley.
‐"Jewel of our valley"?
‐Yeah.
I don't even know
how to take that.
This is a unique restaurant
for Logan.
When you're doing an
international flair restaurant
with all different kind of
flavors from around the world,
you better make it unique.
That is delicious.
Well done.
Whoa.
There's this weird hand
sticking through the thing.
Hello. Bye‐bye.