You know, people are asking
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how they doing?"
"You know, I don't know.
We should check it out."
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
because "Triple D"
joints have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking,
like on this trip.
Those will wreck you.
In San Diego...
Oh!
...a band of brothers bringing
their Asian-inspired eats...
This is what goes
into your pho?
...to the beach.
Dynamite!
In Iowa...
It makes you forget
your mother's cooking.
FIERI: ...this champ is wheeling
and dealing...
What, the whole coop
come with this order?
...out-of-bounds barbecue.
Delicious.
Plus...
Cuckoo.
...outrageous oysters
and crazy combos...
Whatever it is,
it's good.
...in the Big Easy.
Good rub, man.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off-the-hook flavors,
this is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So I'm hanging out
with my buddy Shane
from Hodad's Burgers.
Now, Shane, let's see,
back in 2013,
your dad took me
to OB Noodle House,
which is, what, like,
seven blocks that way?
-Yep.
-All right, Hodad.
This is the joint.
How's the food?
Food is amazing,
and the story is even better.
That's my kind of joint.
FIERI: The Bossman, Mike Hardin,
was a local Ocean Beach legend
who owned Hodad's, one of
"Triple D's" OG joints
until unfortunately
he passed away in 2015.
So since then,
you've taken over.
You're running Hodad's,
and these guys
have opened up a new joint.
Have you been here?
Oh, yeah, OB Noodle House
Bar 1502?
Legit?
Oh, yeah.
Let's go.
Wagyu short ribs,
bar three.
They have a lot of Asian fusion
things, some Vietnamese food.
They have some Korean wings,
really, really cool.
And I got the pork belly taco
right here.
Once they were on "Triple D,"
it blew up even more.
Everybody knows
the Yeng brothers.
They do so much for Ocean Beach.
FIERI: He's talking about Steve
and Kyle Yeng
of Ocean Beach in San Diego.
Wait, what?
Who's the new one?
Oh, he's my younger brother.
Yeah, but he was
in high school.
He was in high school.
I first met these guys
back in 2013
when they were a lone location
a few blocks from the beach.
How did this place come about?
"Triple D"
is just a phenomenon.
The wait got up to be
about 3, 4 hours,
and, like,
"What do we do?
Let's open 7 blocks away,"
so here it is, Bar 1502.
Is it still some of the OB
Noodle House favorites here?
Yep.
Yeah.
You still get
the real-deal pho?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Pho-get about it.
I love pho.
FIERI: This is what goes
into your pho?
Oh, I got to see this.
-All right.
So start it off, first thing up,
loading up the bones.
Uh-huh.
Now we go with oxtails.
Next, we got briskets.
There's a ton of meat.
Yeah, and here is
drop loin,
tendons, salt and rock sugar,
shallots, ginger.
We let this go for about
another 45 minutes.
All this work and effort
makes 20 gallons
worth of broth.
Of concentrated broth.
Wow, what a process,
every day?
Every day.
All right.
Do it up.
Couple layer of our rare
meat in here.
This is how much meat
you put in this bowl?
That's why we call it
the number-one special.
Just like that, it's done.
I just want to try
this broth by itself.
Uh-huh.
♪♪
Unbelievable.
You're gonna have a pretty
tough time
finding it this good.
You've got a new brother
in OB Noodle House, man.
Next thing I'm gonna do
is I'm gonna come back here,
and I'm gonna draw
my mural right on your wall.
Awesome.
♪♪
How's the menu
different here?
We added the Wagyu beef
short ribs right here.
It's one of our top items.
First, we're gonna make
a marinade, soy sauce,
sugar,
grounded ginger,
grounded Asian pear,
grounded onions,
grounded garlic,
sesame oil, white pepper,
toasted sesame seed, honey
and our peanut butter whiskey.
Going to pour our marinade
over our ribs,
gonna leave this
to marinate overnight.
Add some butter, and we're
gonna caramelize
some sliced onions.
We're gonna add
our marinated ribs
on the grill,
couple minutes on each side,
and we're gonna
cut them to small pieces.
We'll garnish it
with a little cilantro.
Here is our Wagyu beef
Korean-style short ribs.
Two Wagyu short ribs!
Here you go.
Try.
These are good.
Kobe ribs?
-Yeah.
Ribs are gangster.
Short ribs are probably just
one of God's greatest gifts
to mankind, man.
You eat it with your hands,
and you're excited to get messy.
WOMAN: They use a really
high-quality Wagyu beef.
They're very tender,
always come out sizzling.
You get the nice char.
You still get that kind of
sweet flavor that comes through.
Dynamite!
STEVE: Marinated with peanut
butter whiskey,
so it give that sweetness.
Where does the peanut
butter whiskey come from?
We have a distillery.
Oh, this will wreck you.
-That's dangerous.
-It's really good.
It does have
a very caramelly roasted --
It's almost like you're eating
Cracker Jacks.
-Yeah.
I'm gonna leaving the car
for a while.
I'm not gonna get towed,
am I?
[ Laughs ]
I dig it, guys.
Now just give me some of those
spicy garlic wings
to go with that whiskey.
Start by just turning
on the fire.
Whoa!
This is a true, real-deal
wok station,
and I'm putting one of these
in the house
when Lori goes on vacation.
Shh.
STEVE: It's pretty hot.
Can't wear a lot of haircare
product and be around that.
Adding some heat right now.
Seriously.
You got the habanero.
How much heat do you like?
Oh, bring it.
Bring it all?
Yeah.
So what are gonna put in?
All of it.
[ Whistles ]
Then we'll bring
some more heat...
So hot...
...Thai chili pepper.
That all cooked down.
Then we strain it,
and you get this liquid.
This is the liquid.
Oh, hot.
[ Whistling ]
Wow, that was warm.
Let me bring in my brother,
Kyle, the wok master.
You're the wok master?
That's what he said.
-Get in here!
-Let's go. Let's go.
-You ready?
-Uh-huh.
Put a little Thai pepper.
Just breathe
with our mouth.
Make sure we don't breathe
with our nose
because otherwise,
it'll burn.
I've been in these kitchens
before.
I know...
Oh!
So a nice little crisp,
quick little sauté.
Uh-huh.
Going to be a little spicy,
but let me know how you like it.
They're smoking hot.
♪♪
Ah.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
It's super flavorful,
good amount of spice to it,
little bit of sweet.
There's a lot of flavor.
I'm impressed.
But I'm not done digging in yet.
Coming up...
So what else is on the menu,
guys?
Taco Tuesday.
...tacos with a twist...
That was mine, Shane.
...and the old family recipe
that put them on the map.
O-M-G in OB.
Welcome to Guido's
House of Meat.
No, that's really not
what it is.
I'm in Ocean Beach
down by San Diego
hanging out with the guys
at the OB Noodle House.
FIERI: A dream locale for Steve
and Kyle Yeng,
Chinese immigrants who have
one heck of a backstory.
My grandparents and my parents
immigrated down to Cambodia
to escape
the Communist war
until they got caught in
the whole Khmer Rouge genocide.
Which sent them to Thailand
where their dad,
Yao Sher Yeng, used
his signature sausage recipe
to move the family to Cali.
What do you think
about these guys, huh?
It's good.
They've done good?
Yeah.
Since we stopped by in 2013,
the Yengs brought in another
brother and opened a new joint,
but they're still cranking out
their dad's killer sausage.
O-M-G in OB.
It's one of the main ingredients
in their off-the-hook
fried rice.
Put a little satay sauce,
chopped sausage,
jumbo shrimps
and some beef strip loins.
Just constantly shaking it,
make sure it doesn't burn,
and you feel the heat?
-I can feel the heat.
♪♪
All the rice is separated.
You do get a little bit
of the heat.
Mm.
All right.
MAN: The food quality
hasn't changed a bit.
The only thing that ever changes
is maybe
they add
something new to the menu.
So what else is on the menu,
guys?
It's San Diego,
and so we have to come up
with a Taco Tuesday,
so we added
the pork belly taco.
KYLE: And the first thing
we're going to make --
the pork belly taco sauce.
We use the bone marrow
from our pho
and scoop the bone marrow
out the beef bones.
Now we're gonna puree this and
add it to our pork belly sauce,
mayo, homemade satay sauce,
homemade sweet chili sauce,
and last, our bone marrow.
Now we can make our marinades.
This is the same marinade
we used for our Korean
short ribs, but this time,
we add a little pineapple juice
to add a little tang
and a little acid.
To make our pickle salad,
we'll sweat the cabbage
and carrot
to draw out the moisture.
Add our pork to our steam
bun, pickle salad.
Add our taco sauce that we made
with bone marrow earlier,
top with cilantro.
Pork belly tacos, bar three.
It's really good, man,
really good.
Try it?
Hey.
That was mine, Shane.
No, I don't want it back now!
There's this really sweet sauce
that's in it,
and it goes really well
with the caramelized pork belly
and pickled vegetables,
just all good.
It's such a good combination
all together.
The soft bun just got
a ton of flavor.
It's always a lot of fun
to have a little
Asian twist with the taco.
You guys have given us
an opportunity of a lifetime.
FIERI: All we did was shine
the light on you.
You had to take it and run
with it, which you've done,
and you've done such a great
job, and people love it.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Keep it up.
Love you guys.
You're gonna have
to pick up the bill.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Shane, you're the best, man.
Thanks for picking up the tab,
and believe me,
I'll be back to see you soon.
Now coming up...
Getting a lot of honey
in there, honey.
...a joint in Iowa that's not
just rocking good barbecue.
They're rolling in it, too.
That's a big Ferris wheel
in Flavortown.
♪♪
You know that
I am a barbecue junkie,
and this pit master
in Des Moines, Iowa,
is so smoking, he's got
a trophy wall to prove it.
My barbecue team, Motley Que,
has gone head-to-head
with him for years,
and I'm not gonna say
who's got more victories.
This is Smokey D's BBQ.
Half-rack, beans and mac.
I am a barbecue guy.
I've known Darren a long time.
He makes you forget
your mother's cooking.
MAN #2: I saw the original
segment on "Triple D,"
made me want to come
try everything out.
You're not disappointed,
and if you leave hungry,
it's your own fault.
FIERI:
Let me tell you something.
Don't enter a barbecue
competition
if this guy is there.
If Captain Barbecue Pork
was a superhero,
he'd live here.
Wow, man, this is crazy.
Darren Warth is his name,
and championship barbecue
is his game.
So three
full-blown smokers,
that's a big Ferris wheel
in Flavortown.
We compete on the barbecue
circuit almost every weekend.
When you're holding
your front door open
with the 2012
American Royal Grand
Champion trophy,
you know you got
a few too many trophies.
Or '13.
Oh, I'm...I'm so sorry.
Stop.
Seriously, I think
my team has two.
Winner, winner,
chicken wing dinner.
So, doctor, hit it up.
Yep.
Let's make a rub --
sugar, salt,
brown sugar, chili powder...
Okay.
...black pepper, paprika...
I like the way you do it.
...onion powder...
Bring it.
...garlic powder,
little cumin,
cayenne pepper.
I'm gonna mix it up,
gonna rub on top.
Okay, to the smoker.
About an hour
and 15 minutes.
Now it's time for the...
Asian glaze.
We have the hoisin sauce,
teriyaki, honey,
white balsamic vinegar,
sriracha, red pepper flake.
Whoa!
♪♪
Delicious.
Little sauce on there.
Stand back.
What, the whole coop
come with this order?
The whole coop.
Give me wing-y.
Dynamite.
Getting a lot of honey
in there, honey.
Great spice, subtle,
not overdone,
mm, it's fantastic, mm.
Let's talk
about the menu here.
Couple menu changes,
we've added some things
like the barbecue egg roll
and the jalapeño tenderloin.
FIERI: Don't forget
the biggest add-on.
That award-winning barbecue
is now rolling out.
[ Horn honks ]
We opened a food truck.
Such a fun addition.
You don't have to go
to the restaurant.
You can find the food truck.
I think it's amazing.
Jalapeño loin up!
FIERI: And everything
on the menu is road-trip ready
like the smoked Philly.
DARREN: Every time I went
to New York City,
I ended up eating
this roast pork Philly,
and it was really good.
We decided to bring it
back to Iowa
and put our own spin in it
by using a smoked pork shoulder.
We're gonna apply
some of our Smokey D's BBQ rub.
It's got salt, sugar, paprika,
a little chili powder.
We're gonna put them
in the smoker.
Cook these at 200 degrees
for about 12 hours.
We're making
our garlic au jus --
onion, fresh garlic,
Worcestershire, water, beef
paste, red wine,
fresh thyme,
fresh oregano, fresh basil.
Let this simmer 2 hours.
Start with a really nice white
crispy roll, peppers and onions.
Take our smoked pork shoulder
and then dip it down
in that garlic au jus
and off to the flattop,
peppers and onions on there
with provolone cheese.
Pork Philly for Jason.
Right here.
Tender meat, first thing you hit
is the peppers and the onions
and then slow-smoked pork.
It's very good.
The pork just gives it
a nice mellow flavor.
The au jus is amazing.
It just gives it a whole nother
level of flavor complexity,
and if I could,
I would drink it with a straw.
FIERI: And he's added another
meal to the menu, too.
Nothing like a little barbecue
in the a.m.
You wouldn't think of barbecue
for breakfast,
but it's my favorite thing.
FIERI: Like the walking biscuits
and gravy.
We've got fresh ground
pork trimmings.
We're gonna add
two of my favorite
competition barbecue rubs.
Add a little salt
and pepper to it,
and then we get our sage.
We mix that by hand.
Now we're gonna brown off
the sausage.
We're gonna make our roux.
We're gonna add some flour,
heavy cream, salt and pepper.
Let it cook.
Scoop of this gravy
in the bottom,
and then we're gonna cut up
one of our homemade biscuits,
gonna put that in the cup,
a little more gravy on the top,
top it with some bacon.
Everybody likes bacon.
Our walking biscuits and gravy.
Order for Tom!
Thanks, sir.
MAN #3: It's contained.
It doesn't get all over
my shirt, creamy, delicious.
The biscuits weren't dry,
awesome.
The best part is there's bacon
on the top, delicious.
God knows there's no calories,
so that's great.
I heard everything
is calorie-free
as long as you stay
in the specially atmospheric
pressure zone here
of the Pork Colosseum,
but when you leave,
you're on your own.
The food is legit, man.
You are the real deal.
Thank you.
No wonder you win
all the time.
Take a break!
Go on vacation!
Take, like, 10 years off.
Actually, don't.
The nation needs
that killer barbecue.
Maybe just bring your
"A" game down to a B-plus
to give everybody else a chance?
And coming up in New Orleans...
This is what
the show is about.
...a place that got
a second chance
and came back better
than ever.
Look what you got
going now, man.
FIERI: Back in 2010,
I went to this joint
in New Orleans
about 3 miles outside
of the French Quarter.
Now, Katrina had hit hard,
and it took him almost
5 years to reopen,
but they got down to business,
and they're still going strong.
One Legend in the window.
This is Katie's.
Since I'm from here,
I know where good food is.
I can say this is
one of the best.
I think "Triple D" showed
the world
what Katie's was capable of
and what New Orleans
was capable of after Katrina.
FIERI: After the storm,
owner Scot Craig
had his work cut out for him.
What happened?
7 feet of water.
As high as the doorjambs?
Yeah.
SCOT: You reopen a business
after something
as big as Hurricane Katrina.
Then "Triple D" comes along,
and it literally changed
my life overnight.
We had a line of people out
the door the very next day.
It's just an amazing thing.
How do you
explain the food?
We call it
neighborhood cuisine.
What are we making?
Our crawfish beignet.
Here is our dough.
We're gonna put
our buttercream reduction,
whole milk mozzarella,
Provel cheese, cheddar cheese,
Louisiana crawfish
and pickled jalapeños.
You're making me
a calzone!
If it was a calzone,
it would go in a pizza oven.
Guy and I did not agree
that it was a beignet.
You're gonna call
that a beignet?
Because I can do anything
I want to do!
Any fried dough, no matter what
fried dough it is, is a beignet.
Cuckoo.
It's a beignet!
I'm telling you, man!
Well, whatever it is,
it's good.
I mean, it's fried dough
stuffed with cheese
and crawfish.
It's nice.
Thank you, dude.
Beignet.
FIERI: And he's still slinging
local seafood
like chargrilled oysters.
SCOT: You hit them with
an oyster margarine
because butter will burn.
It's got lots of garlic,
white pepper, black pepper
and then Italian seasoning,
a little bit of Parmesan cheese.
You let that melt for a second.
FIERI:
But he didn't stop there.
Coach Slessinger,
he's the head coach
of the University
of New Orleans basketball.
We were having the chargrilled
oysters one night, and he said,
"Dude, these really
need a sauce,"
so I came back here, and I made
a creamy cheese sauce.
It's almost like you're making
an Alfredo,
heavy cream, Parmesan cheese,
Provel cheese, spinach.
Now I'm gonna put some shrimp
in it, house-made bacon.
We're letting the sauce
just kind of simmer here,
oysters Slessinger dedicated
to Coach Mark Slessinger.
I had talked a lot of trash
to Scot,
and he came back
with an incredible mix
of Provel,
spinach, shrimp.
It's a whole meal unto itself.
These oysters are
absolutely amazing,
the creaminess,
the cheesiness.
There's also shrimp on top.
You get, like,
double the goodness.
All right. What are we doing
to this pork butt?
It looks like you're making
a nice little dry rub for it.
We got
a little onion powder.
Okay.
Garlic, lots of that.
Cayenne.
The hot stuff, a little black
pepper, some white pepper,
salt, cumin, paprika
and then the old secret
ingredient over here
that if I tell you,
I got to kill you, so...
Cajun seasoning.
He busted me on that one.
We just stir it up.
Then I'm gonna come over here,
boneless pork butt.
I make some buttons.
Very nice.
And I come
with a little parsley,
then hit it
with a little garlic.
My dad taught me that
when I was a kid.
Never saw the parsley move.
Spoon on the rub.
Generous application,
rub it down.
All right.
Let's roll.
Used to have a little unit
like this.
That's how
I started smoking.
Tell you what,
it's perfect for us,
between 230 and 250,
an hour and a half a pound.
[ Whistles ]
Oh, that's beautiful.
That's about 13 hours
right there, beautiful.
Good rub, man.
FIERI: But that little smoker's
not cutting it anymore.
We were cooking at the time
maybe six or seven pork
butts a day.
Now it's about 40.
FIERI:
Good thing he's smoking so many
because those pork butts
are going into
the Boudreaux pizza...
Impressive.
The pork is right where it
should be, not too much smoke.
It's fantastic.
You rocked that out.
Right.
Nice job.
...and into this
crazy concoction.
Locals call it the Legend.
Starts with a barbecued
shrimp butter,
which is reduced
Worcestershire sauce,
a bunch of butter,
Provel cheese.
It's a great, smoky flavor.
We're gonna add the cream,
black pepper,
little cayenne pepper,
fresh Louisiana shrimp
and pulled pork.
I hollow out the end
of a French bread,
and then I stuff it with all of
the stuff we combined together.
It sounds odd to combine
barbecued shrimp
and pulled pork,
but it's one of our top sellers.
We got a Legend up.
The Legend is, like,
something that's not too heavy.
It leaves you totally satisfied.
Very rich and smoky flavor,
and it's a melting pot
of deliciousness.
♪♪
Guy makes it a game-changer.
Since then, I've opened up
another restaurant.
We increased our capacity
from 75 to now almost 150.
WOMAN #2:
The addition with the upstairs
made it a little bit easier
to get into
because after "Triple D,"
it got a little crowded.
This is
what the show is about.
You came back.
You helped out.
You rebuilt.
It took you 4 1/2 years,
but look what you got
going now, man.
Thanks, dude.
That's the truth.
I love good old success stories
like the Yeng brothers
in San Diego
whose noodle house is turning
into a noodle empire...
[ Cheering ]
FIERI: ...and Smokey D's
award-winning barbecue
now rolling all over Iowa,
and of course comeback Katie's
in New Orleans
where their French-inspired
seafood still reigns supreme,
and we'll have plenty more
stories to tell next time
on "Triple-D Nation."
OB Elementary.
Was it called
OB Elementary?
Ocean Beach Elementary.
When you would leave the house,
just you and your brother
and your guys' dad
going on the water,
would your mom say,
"OB careful"?
Just let me...
I mean, let me just
take a moment, okay?