Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
It's time to eat.
...we're all over the map...
There's a lot going on
in this thing.
...picking up
some first-class flavor.
That's no joke right there,
folks.
From incredible Italian
in Delaware...
Oh, that's double fist bump
right there, pal.
...to a quick Middle Eastern
spin in San Diego.
It's like, raining chicken in
Flavortown right there, buddy.
And in Vancouver, Canada...
You just took it to the next
level, just so you know.
...a pizza joint
charting all-new territory.
That's a destination bite.
People come here to get that.
Because you won't find that
anywhere else.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in San Diego,
California,
in the Kearny Mesa area,
and I got to tell you,
ladies and gentlemen, the food
revolution is alive and well.
I mean we are finding
our favorite
ethnic foods everywhere.
I'm here at a strip mall
looking for
some Middle Eastern food.
This is Tahini Street Food.
I got a steak shawarma
rice bowl.
Real authentic Middle Eastern
food. I've been hooked.
I could come here every day.
Cumato salad.
Six-piece falafel.
And I love Mahmoud and Osama
and all the crew here.
FIERI: That's high-school
buddies Osama Shabaik
and Mahmoud Barkawi,
who started out as a lawyer
and aspiring cop,
but couldn't resist the pull
of their families'
Egyptian and Syrian cuisine.
So they started a side hustle
that exploded into this.
San Diego, you find taco shops
all the time, right?
-True.
-You don't find shawarma.
FIERI: So this is
a Middle Eastern taco shop?
-Pretty much.
-For the most part, yeah.
We stole the recipes
from our mothers.
We'll stack the shawarmas
in-house.
I got a chicken
shawarma sandwich.
Fries inside.
Chicken shawarma is definitely
one of the dishes
that I order often.
All of the flavors
just drizzling down,
marinating as they cook it.
They shave off the meat right in
front of you. It's delicious.
All right.
What are we making first?
The marinade for
the chicken shawarma.
The first thing
we have is yogurt.
Fresh blended oranges
and lemon.
Seed, pith, everything.
The whole nine.
I haven't seen this one yet.
Tomato paste.
Red-pepper paste.
Soybean oil.
White vinegar.
Lemon juice.
Black pepper.
Turmeric.
Good call.
You know your way
around the kitchen.
I've dabbled.
Paprika.
Got it.
Cumin.
Curry powder.
Garlic powder.
Salt.
Onion powder.
A little cayenne.
Yeah.
And some ground ginger.
Got it. Now, is it
all chicken thigh?
Yes. Now we'll throw
the marinade in here.
It'll help to break it down
with that yogurt.
And then we'll start
to build the rotisserie.
Watch me, now.
Two pieces of chicken!
Ah-ha-ha!
And three pieces
of chicken now!
We're actually gonna sneak
in some lamb fat.
Hold please.
It's definitely a secret
from back home.
It actually melts off
as the vertical boiler
is cooking the chicken.
A couple more pieces on top, and
then the onion and the tomato.
And then this will go
to the vertical rotisserie.
The first layer takes roughly
about 45 minutes.
Next up?
We make our own
tahini sauce.
First, we'll start we the pure
sesame-seed paste, sriracha...
You don't see that so much
in the Middle Eastern menu.
Not at all.
...water, lemon juice...
Yeah, yeah.
...salt, garlic powder,
cumin of course, cayenne pepper,
citric salt, black pepper.
Get the arm workout in.
It's good to go.
Wow!
I'll have a bowl of that.
[ Laughs ]
So now we're gonna build
the chicken shawarma.
I can have it in a bowl,
I can have it as a salad,
or I can have it as a wrap.
We make our own pita bread.
I'll have it as a wrap.
You got it.
So this is yeast, sugar, salt,
flour, and wheat flour.
Yes, sir.
And a little bit of olive oil.
We'll set it in here.
Whoa!
Look at that!
That's where the magic happens.
-Little hot though.
-Whoa!
Okay, there's steam
coming out of the side of it.
No can beat-a this pita.
It's moist.
It's got great texture
on the outside.
Tender on the inside.
The whole wheat adds
some really nice body.
Dynamite.
It's like, raining chicken in
Flavortown right there, buddy.
Make sure I have
extra lamb fat.
Stuff these chicken.
French fries.
Garlic sauce.
Sriracha tahini.
Parsley mix.
[ Whistles ]
Tomatoes.
Pickled cucumbers.
Sriracha tahini on top.
That's all she wrote.
♪♪
The silence is killing me.
What's the word?
We'll be back
after these messages.
[ Laughter ]
The chicken...
It's tender.
The garlic sauce and the
sriracha tahini together...
Great acidity.
A touch of heat.
The vegetable crunch
and the freshness of that...
A little salt and crunch
from the French fries.
I mean, just everywhere
you turn inside this...
It's killer.
I got your chicken
shawarma pita.
It's amazing. There's a lot
going on in this thing.
It's extremely,
extremely delicious.
I really love the chicken.
It has so much flavor in it.
The flavor combination
is amazing,
and it goes so well
together.
If you come to San Diego,
you will definitely run
into Melissa d'Arabian
and family.
Melissa won
"Food Network Star."
What season was that, five?
Five.
A judge on
"Guy's Grocery Games."
I love Middle Eastern food.
Do we know what true
Middle Eastern
is out here
on the West Coast?
There's not a lot.
Yeah, I know that much.
Order up. Full order of tahini
fries with steak shawarma.
The San Diego food scene
is amazing,
but are you surprised
to find something like Tahini?
Oh, for sure.
This is a Chef Works team.
For years,
Marcie and her team
have been making me
the coolest chef coats.
You deal with chefs
from all over the world.
What do you think?
I think it's delicious.
The falafel is on point.
For sure.
I got a falafel salad ready.
This falafel is crispy
from the outside,
but when you bit in it,
it's green and fluffy.
Ohh. It's so good.
What's the next dish?
Now we'll be making the falafel,
more of the Egyptian way,
where we use fava beans
instead of garbanzo beans.
They're a little higher
in protein.
Huh.
And we'll go ahead
and throw the dill first.
That's a big "dill." [deal]
Parsley. Chives.
Cilantro.
A little bit of red onions.
Fresh garlic.
Salt. Black pepper.
Cumin.
Ground coriander.
Don't tell anybody.
I won't.
It's between us.
Cayenne pepper.
Fava beans that
have been soaked.
One grind?
We do it twice.
A little baking soda?
Just a pinch.
It helps create
a little pillowiness.
This is my little falafel
scooper.
Another one of Mom's secrets
is Just give it that little
pinky poke.
'Cause it helps it cook
in the middle.
Donut falafel.
Fry this off, 350,
in soybean oil.
Yeah.
And then we'll build
the salad.
Exactly.
Tomatoes on there.
Red onion.
Some bell peppers.
Olives.
The sriracha tahini.
pepperoncinis.
Turnips.
Feta cheese.
All right, we're down
to three.
Well, I'm sorry,
I was waiting for the salad.
He didn't...
This is such
a righteous falafel.
So much flavor,
so much texture,
so much goin' on.
That's how I want
my falafel from now on.
And you get these
pickled vegetables.
The crunch.
The brininess.
A little bit of spice
coming through
from that sriracha tahini.
The saltiness
of that feta...
That's no joke
right there, folks.
Outstanding.
Thank you, sir.
Falafel salad.
This falafel is rich,
and the sauces bring out all
the flavors of the vegetables.
YOUNG WOMAN: I'm a vegetarian
and gluten-free,
so often we turn to falafel
and usually it's
the traditional chick peas.
And this has like
a new spin to it.
It's incredible.
-I have nothing to add.
-Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
Order of haloumi cheese
sticks ready.
Best Middle Eastern food
I've ever had.
It looks good, it tastes good.
What else do you need?
This is the real deal, man.
Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
FIERI: Up next, a righteous
pizza place up in Vancouver...
That's gorgeous, man.
...rockin' out crazy combos...
Lamb & The Grapes.
That's my new band name.
...and putting normal pies
to shame.
I don't think I could have
dreamed that pizza up,
but I'm so glad
that I got to try it.
♪♪
Now, typically on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
we do not shoot joints
that are only open at night,
but we're here
in Vancouver, Canada,
and we heard about a pizza joint
where they're making their pies
with a bunch of enthusiasm
and creativity,
and just a little bit
of craziness,
just like their owner.
This is Corduroy Pie Company.
Sausage and peppers, Brussels
sprouts, for table three.
WOMAN: There's a lot of pizza
in Vancouver,
and I think Corduroy
is different.
Bacon and potato for table four.
Super innovative, creative pies
that are always top-notch.
Graham's a good dude.
He cares a lot about
the ingredients that he uses.
FIERI: That would be
Chef Graham Marceau,
who traded working
in fine dining
for a different slice of life.
Had you owned a pizza parlor
before this?
I worked in several
pizza shops.
You worked in several?
I've flown on
several airplanes,
I'm not a pilot.
That's all I have.
I'm gonna go after that.
Good night, folks.
So I just jumped in.
We didn't want to just do
pepperoni and mushroom,
so we started curing stuff,
started doing weird stuff.
Lamb sausage.
I got to say, the lamb sausage
is my favorite.
It's quite rich,
but then he cuts all that
with a little bit of acidity
with these grapes.
It's got some spice to it.
It's fresh. It's delicious.
We're gonna do
a lamb sausage pizza.
Lamb sausage?
Correct.
What is your crust?
We take a note out of the
sourdough-bread-baking book.
We basically start with this.
It's called a poolish.
I get foolish
with the poolish.
Ice-cold water here,
some baker's yeast,
on top of our poolish here.
Okay.
Sugar.
Salt.
Canola oil.
Full-strength bread flour.
Whole-wheat flour.
My man.
We're gonna mix this
for 10 minutes, rest it,
then we're gonna mix it
for another 10 minutes.
Bring it out.
We're gonna portion.
And then it goes in the fridge
for 24 hours.
Okay.
So now we're making
our house-made lamb sausage.
Let's see it.
We ground the lamb shoulder.
Some salt.
Fresh-chopped oregano.
Chili flakes.
Ground black pepper.
Minced garlic.
Let it set overnight.
Let the flavors
come together.
What else is on this pie?
Sweet onions.
A little bit of Sicilian
olive oil on the bottom.
Okay.
Olive oil on the top.
Fresh thyme.
Black pepper.
I really like how you just put
the thyme there,
and the pepper there.
We got some salt.
It's the flair and essence
that makes it.
So we'll mix it up.
Roast at 650
for about an hour.
Okay.
A little bit of flour
on top of the dough.
I like to touch the bottom
on the board,
flip it, and then flip it back,
and then we know
the whole thing is coated.
Got it.
And just start
with the fingers.
Treat it like a baby.
-Do you have kids?
-I don't.
Yeah, you don't do that
to your baby.
[ Laughter ]
I just put it on the back
of my hands.
I use my thumbs to guide it.
That's exactly
how I throw dough.
Gorgeous lookin' skin.
So this is a white sauce --
crème fraîche thinned out
with a whipping cream,
Parmesan cheese,
smoked mozzarella.
Here's our lamb sausage.
Roasted onions.
Look at those.
Seedless grapes.
You just took it to the next
level, just so you know.
This is a good one.
Pepper. Some salt.
Fresh green kale.
All right. In the oven.
-Yes.
-650.
Give it a little shake.
Shimmy shimmy cocoa pop.
Six minutes.
Bada-bing, bada-boom.
Gorgeous, man.
Fresh basil.
Sicilian olive oil
on there.
Time to eat.
It's delicious.
That lamb sausage on pizza
is one of my new favorites.
And the lamb
and the grape combo...
And the kale coming through,
which gives it
a really nice textural...
You get this nice char.
I don't think I could have
dreamed that pizza up,
but I'm so glad
that I got to try it.
It's imaginative,
and it's delicious.
That's a destination pie.
People come here to get that.
Because you won't find that
anywhere else.
I got a lamb sausage
for the bar.
MAN: The lamb sausage itself
is amazing.
It has that flavor that you want
without that gaminess.
It's definitely
a little bit different.
It's got the grapes on there,
which is something
that I would never really think
to put on a pizza.
Nice and crispy crust.
Lovely to bite into.
Good pizza, good room.
FIERI: There's some funk goin'
on in the room, right?
This is like,
some grandpa's old garage.
It's so cozy.
It's all wood.
It feels like a ski lodge
meets a biker bar.
-Someone's basement.
-Your basement.
Technically it is my basement.
'Cause I live upstairs.
Okay,
you had me at that.
It's laid back. There's craft
beer, craft food, craft pizza.
Lamb & The Grapes.
That's my new band name.
Our newest album
"Piece 'o the Pie."
All right, Chef,
one more pie?
Done.
Amatriciana.
The amatriciana is excellent.
It's a little bit salty,
a little bit of heat,
a little bit of sweetness.
I'll see you in a minute.
You want a piece?
Good, let me make you
one up here in just a second.
I'll be right back
with this.
Aw, man.
[ Laughter ]
Welcome back. We're hanging out
at Corduroy Pie Company
in Vancouver, Canada, eh?
[ Laughs ]
We are about creative pies,
eclectic pies,
scratch-made pies.
The ingredients
that they use here,
it's just something
that's totally different.
FIERI:
Like this cheeky feast.
An amatriciana in the window.
The amatriciana is
my go-to pie for sure.
It's based off of a classic
Italian pasta dish.
There's lot of sweet onions
on there, pancetta,
lots of the roasted garlic.
It's so good.
Okay.
So what are we into?
We're doing
an amatriciana pizza.
Which is of my favorite
pasta dishes.
Which -- it does not
go on pizza.
No.
So I'm just here
to let you know that.
But here in Canada,
we break the rules.
Everybody says that
about the Canadians,
"rule-breakers," right?
So we got the cheeks
off some pigs.
Guanciale.
These cheeks,
not the other ones.
What we do is, we cure them
with kosher salt, sugar,
fennel seeds,
chili flakes,
black pepper, bay leaf,
freshly grated nutmeg.
They're gonna go over...
How long is this gonna go?
A week in the fridge,
it's gonna cure.
We're gonna cook it slow
for probably about
a half an hour,
45 minutes.
Okay. So now the sauce.
We got our diced pork cheek.
We'll slowly render this out
in the oven.
Let me just tell you
something.
The dry brine that
you put on that...
Bro. I'd just sit with
a bowl of those.
Ohh.
Diced onion.
Oregano leaves.
Minced garlic.
And chili flakes.
A little stir-sky.
So, we're gonna in...
Once our onions
are rendered out,
we can add our tomato sauce.
It goes down
for how much longer?
For about an hour.
At 650. Okay.
We're ready to roll.
We got our finished
amatriciana sauce here,
Parmesan cheese, pickled onions
that we pickle in-house,
cured cheek...
A cheeky fellow.
...whole-roasted
garlic confit,
aged mozzarella cheese,
fresh oregano,
a little salt,
fresh cracked pepper.
Do you want to give me
the pipe wrench?
I'll go get it.
Pipe wrench?
Yeah, so I can take
the kitchen sink.
That's the only thing
that's not on here.
Buda-dum-bum.
I'll be here all week.
Six minutes in the oven.
Sizzle sizzle.
Like Mount Vesuvius --
the volcano in Flavortown.
Some basil going on here.
Sicilian olive oil.
She's-a ready.
Here we go.
The sauce,
with the cured pork jowl,
I want that on everything.
I don't know if you can offer it
as a salad dressing,
but I'll take some.
The confit garlic...
A genius touch.
You're taking one of the most
beloved Italian pasta dishes,
and go put it on a pizza.
I would come in to try it just
to prove that it didn't work.
You put it on a pizza
just to prove that it does.
Outstanding.
Thanks, man.
Amatriciana.
Table eleven.
The amatriciana is definitely
my favorite.
The red sauce is not
your typical pizza tomato sauce.
It's spicy, cheesy.
You gonna describe Graham,
or the pizza?
Both.
WOMAN:
It's just pizza with heart.
You're not gonna be
disappointed.
A bacon and potato.
30 seconds away.
Corduroy Pie is definitely
leading the charge.
FIERI: In the world of doing
pizza and doing pizza right,
that's legit.
Thanks, man.
Well done, my friend.
Thank you very much.
Well done.
FIERI: Coming up,
in Wilmington, Delaware...
I can't wait.
...a legit Brooklyn chef...
[ Raspy voice ] You'll be
brought into the family.
...at the funkiest of spots...
It's so entertaining
just to look around.
...makes for an unforgettable
Italian immersion.
That is flavor city
right there.
♪♪
You know, around the country,
every big major city
has got a Little Italy.
So, here's the story --
the chef has got
a restaurant in New York City.
The governor of New York says,
"Hey, you know what,
I think you should pack it up,
head on down to
Wilmington, Delaware,
and establish the Little Italy
down there."
I guess the governor kind
of made an offer
he couldn't refuse.
This is Luigi Vitrone's
Pastabilities.
Gnocchi
with marinara sauce.
Luigi is an amazing chef.
Everything is always
incredibly fresh.
Raviolis comin' out.
He out-does himself every time.
When people come here,
what type of Italian food
are they getting?
Regional Italian cuisine,
ingredients from
the old country.
The authenticity
is key to us.
FIERI: And you know it's legit
when the recipes go way back
into Luigi Vitrone's
family cookbook
and have become staples here
for the last 30 years.
Arancini.
Appetizer.
Arancini
is a fried ball of cheesy rice.
We serve it with the marinara
sauce on the side.
It's famous for the huge chunks
of garlic.
It's absolutely
my favorite thing.
-What are we gonna make first?
-The arancini risotto.
-I'm a big arancini fan.
-Yeah.
VITRONE: We're gonna
use some olive oil.
We're gonna make a sofrito.
A little bit of fresh
chopped garlic,
mirepoix of onions,
carrots, and celery.
-And fennel frond?
-Right.
Salt and pepper.
Arborio rice.
I like to get each kernel
coated in the oil.
Let's just forget the arancini.
I'll have the risotto.
Italian parsley, basil,
and fresh rosemary.
Choppin' that fresh
every morning.
Sometimes twice a day.
A little bit of milk.
Chicken stock we make
from scratch.
We use chicken bones,
mirepoix,
bay leaves, rosemary,
thyme, parsley stems.
Once it comes to a boil,
let it simmer for about
an hour and a half.
And then we strain it.
And it's stock and stir
and stock and stir?
Finish it with
some cold butter,
Parmigiano-Reggiano,
and that's it.
-Next up?
-The marinara sauce.
California tomatoes.
In honor probably of me
being here.
Salt and pepper.
Dry oregano.
Fresh basil.
Extra-virgin olive oil
from the old country.
I'd expect nothing less.
Garlic.
Nice big pieces.
Italian flat parsley.
Right into the tomatoes.
You're an animal.
Let this cook down, and then
next thing we'll do
is make the arancini.
Right.
Okay. So we make
a little ball.
We take some of
the Italian Gorgonzola.
Another ball.
We havin' a ball.
A little flour.
Oh, yeah.
That's an arancini, buddy.
A beaten egg,
and into our breadcrumbs.
We get them nice
and golden brown
so it looks just like an orange.
"Arancini,"
Italian, "orange."
Some of the marinara sauce
that we just made.
[ Speaks Italian ]
It's nice and creamy.
Wow. You made a point to talk
about that Gorgonzola
being the traditional,
the imported.
That is Gorgonzola, baby.
The rice is still al dente.
You got a great ratio
of creamy interior
to great crunch
on the outside.
That's a really well-balanced
arancini.
Now we hit it with a little bit
of the marinara.
Mmm.
Delicious.
A good amount of garlic.
A lot of tomato.
And the extra-virgin olive oil
that you have there
really carries that through.
Delicious. Mmm.
Two arancinis.
MAN: You'll find arancinis
in many places,
but here,
they do a terrific job.
It's so tender,
you barely have to chew it.
And the marinara sauce is nice
and garlicky. It's killer.
FIERI: This is far
from a chain restaurant.
How do you explain it?
Old-school chef.
The ambience.
The history of it.
It's so entertaining
just to look around
and see what
you're gonna find.
The peacock may be
my favorite so far.
And the black ceiling tiles
with the lights and...
to whatever he has on the walls.
VITRONE: It's a funky apartment
in Milan, Italy, in 1970.
There's not a better way
to explain that.
Luigi has been cooking for me
for 29 years.
He's my buddy.
I come here to see him, too.
Favorite thing on the menu?
Veal, veal, veal.
Next we're gonna make the veal
scallopini rollantini
with the marsala wine
and mushroom sauce.
And fresh homemade pasta.
Of course we would.
It's veal wrapped around Italian
meats and cheese, mushrooms,
and a nice gravy.
It's fabulous.
VITRONE:
We have milk-fed veal.
We use the loin, which we're
gonna pound out a little bit.
And then we're gonna
stuff them
with some Italian delicacy
meats and cheeses.
Prosciutto.
Some capicola.
And soppressata
and provolone.
This is for us to snack on
while we're getting ready
to make the dish?
-Mm-hmm.
-Fantastic.
We got a little bit
of beaten egg here.
Just a little binder
to keep it together
when it's inside
of the veal roll-up.
Right.
We just give it a little roll.
Lightly dredge here
in the flour.
And then, from the egg wash
right into into the sautée pan.
Right.
You can do this with chicken.
You can do it with
pork tenderloin.
The pastabilities...
The pastabilities
are endless.
So, the mushrooms are in,
and the butter is in.
Salt and pepper.
And now we're gonna de-glaze it
with a little bit
of the marsala.
Marsala wine.
A little chicken broth
that we made.
That is flavor city
right there.
Please tell me
you're buying the demi.
No, no, it's homemade.
I want to know where
the other kitchen is.
I think if I go underneath
the floor,
there's a whole
kitchen of elves.
We have a homemade
fettuccine.
-And that's all she wrote.
-That's all she wrote.
I can't wait.
Here's our veal
scallopini rollantini.
Gorgeous.
A little red cabbage,
parsley, carrot,
and a little orchid.
You always need
your orchid.
Mangia!
I'll tell you...
I've had more bad veal dishes
than I've had good.
The amount of time that you
had that in the pan...
I'm not judging, but worried
that it was gonna be
a little dry,
maybe a little overcooked.
It's none of those things.
It's is fantastic.
It's tender.
You got a lot of that salt
coming through
from that hard provolone.
You didn't put a lot
of seasoning into it.
Because there's all that
super seasoning coming through.
From all the charcuterie that's
inside, tender mushrooms...
It's not all marsala.
A nice balance.
I have to do this,
I apologize.
Mangia!
Oh, that's double fist bump
right there, pal.
Thank you.
It's fantastic.
Veal marsala.
I love the veal.
I love that sauce
with the mushrooms.
It was so tender, I just used
my fork as my knife.
Clean as a whistle.
Ravioli. Marina sauce.
When you walk in,
you feel like you're at home.
I've never been disappointed
in anything
I've ever eaten here.
FIERI: It's part a history tour,
it's part of a floor show,
it's part
of a meet-and-greet
with a local celebrity,
but what it is has to be --
it has to be real-deal food,
and that's real-deal.
Watch out for this guy.
[ Raspy voice ] You'll be
brought into the family.
♪♪
So that's it for this edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
If you want to find the recipes
from some of the joints
we visit, well, go to
foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I didn't know that you could
use the fava.
Yeah?
I like it with a fine
Chianti myself.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Smacking lips ]
Sorry, I had to,
I had to, I had to.
I can't hear "fava bean"
and not do that.
[ Laughter ]