You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one
joint you checked out
in that one city when
you were doing 'Triple D' --
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Car engine revs ]
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is
ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
[ Car engine revs ]
Like on this trip.
Are you guys hungry?
CROWD: Yeah!
The whole Fieri family is
headed back to Jamaica...
That's exactly
how I remember it.
...to hit up a jerk joint
we've been drooling
over for years...
I could seriously
eat until I pass out.
...plus an old-school
cafeteria outside Atlanta...
This is one of the most unique
places we've ever been to.
...serving up
a southern smorgasbord...
That would be good
on a flip flop.
...an Austin, Texas
sandwich shop...
Wah!
Look at that.
...nudging in
on my namesake...
Knuckle Sandwich?
That's my line.
...and...
[ Fire truck siren wails ]
This guy
rolls out.
...a smoking hot barbecue spot
in Salt Lake City.
It's nuts.
It's gonzo.
It's unhooked.
It's "off the hook,"
Pat.
Familiar faces,
new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, it was
six years ago.
We had
an awesome cruise.
And now
you are captain.
Alright,
Ryder.
And we're
back in Jamaica
to hit up one of
our favorite joints.
This is
Ocho Rios Jerk Centre.
Oh yeah!       Yeah!
♪♪
Jerk platter.
MAN: Very authentic.
You can come here
and get that Jamaican
taste in your mouth.
It is really, really
off the chain.
I don't think Jerk Centre
has any competition
since
"Triple D" came.
Six years ago,
we did a cruise,
and I brought Hunter and
Ryder and Jules and Lori,
and we found
the Ocho Rios Jerk Centre.
We had a blast.
Everything
is delicious.
People that
get off the ship,
like, this isn't within
walking distance.
There's
a lot of tourists
that won't even know
about this place.
Wouldn't even
know to come here.
Right.
I could seriously
eat until I pass out.
This time, I'm bringing back
60 of my cousins.
I got aunts, I got uncles,
I got everybody.
They're gonna
love it.
And the man responsible for
feeding my extended family
is chef and owner
Kevin White.
Are you guys hungry?
CROWD: Yeah!
GUY: And when we hit this
place up the first time,
Lori and I got a lesson
on their signature sauce.
So, what are we
gonna make, man?
Jerk sauce.
The jerk sauce to
marinate the pork?
To marinate
the pork.
It's a special
blend of seasoning.
Let's go,
first thing.
Pimento.
Pimento?
Yes.
Hold on
a second.
Pimento beans?
Yes, sir.
Natural allspice,
onions.
Garlic.
And this is real
Jamaican ginger.
Real
Jamaican ginger?
Yes, strongest ginger
in the entire region.
Whole thing.
Very strong.
[ Whistles ]
Scotch
bonnet pepper.
Don't touch those.
Stem, seeds,
everything?
Everything, man.
Gives it the body,
gives it the flavor.
Okay.
You're gonna
add the scallion.
Beef fat.
Add some
water to it.
[ Blender whirs ]
And add some salt to
it and some sugar.
Cane sugar?
Yeah.
Can we taste that?
That's delicious.
Is that good?
[ Strained voice ]
Hot, though.
Hot, man.
Ooh.
I wasn't sweating
enough already.
Alright.
Bring out the pork.
Go!
Wow.
We're gonna
score this now
so it can absorb the
seasoning much better.
Alright, now we are ready
to add our seasoning.
Dry rub
and the wet rub.
That is crazy.
Okay, roll it up
like you're rolling up
your sleeping bag at pig camp.
I cannot wait
to try this.
It's gonna marinate
for 12 hours and then
we go on the grill.
Yeah.
Got it.
The pork is laid on top
of a sweet wood long,
which is covered
with aluminum zinc,
and just cook
over open flame
for about
three, four hours.
Look at that.
Just like that.
The foil with
some sauce in it.
♪♪
That is
awesome.
You dip it?
Mm-hmm.
Mmm.
The flavor
is intense.
Not super, super spicy,
but it is hot.
I got to be honest.
I've had
a lot of Jamaican food.
I don't think I've had
any that flavorful.
Thank you.
It's delicious
I've made
a lot of jerk myself.
I've been a jerk,
but...
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my gosh.
Is it
what the boys remembered?
Exactly
how I remember it.
And so was
the rest of the jerk.
That
marinated chicken.
I remember
this chicken
as the best chicken
I've ever had.
This is actually like
the best meal ever.
Out of all
the meals you've had,
you think this one
is your favorite?
This would be
top five for me.
I was scared it
wasn't gonna be as
good as last time,
but this blows it
out of the water.
This will change the way
you ever think about jerk.
It's amazing.
Jerk chicken
is awesome.
It doesn't have
too much spice,
seasoned right
down to the bones.
MAN: Been coming
here for a while.
Standard hasn't dropped.
It's just improved.
GUY:
What's your favorite?
This is
my new favorite.
The goat.
The goat's
outrageous.
GUY: Love me
some curry goat.
We don't have
curry goat on the boat.
Wow.
First we start with
local ram goat,
add some curry,
a bit of salt,
and then we have
a special blend
of all-purpose
seasoning.
This marinates for
about 12 hours.
And we let it
sit and simmer
for about 20 minutes
before we add
carrots and potatoes.
Our famous
curry goat.
Oh.
What do you think,
Socks?
Delicious.
I love curry goat.
Tender, mild,
the way I like it.
Just like grandma
used to give to me.
What are you having?
What is it?
Oh, is that
the fried...
Festival.
Sop that
into the curry.
So good.
You can
make these things.
They're just
so good.
GUY: That's why they
call them "festival."
LORI: It's a festival
in your mouth.
Like a donut.
I'm gonna
eat all of them.
We start
with flour mix.
Salt, sugar,
corn meal,
vanilla, water,
and we mix.
Just roll it,
and then
you stretch.
Then you fry.
Festival pick up!
GUY: Delicious?
Yeah, man.
Festival, man.
HUNTER: You crave this
when you leave,
and you go back home.
No restaurant
is the same.
Hunter's saying
exactly right.
You can't eat
enough of it,
then you're full
and you got to get
back on the ship.
And the moment you
get back on the ship,
you're craving
more of it.
This is the beauty
of Triple D Nation.
I come find these joints,
come back years later,
see what happens,
and you get to enjoy
every bite of it.
Can't beat that.
I told you
I'd be back.
[ Laughs ]
And that's no joke.
As soon as we got
back to the ship,
we were all craving
that jerk all over again.
Now, coming up,
outside Atlanta...
Does anybody ever do
the John Belushi and --
...an old-school cafeteria
angling for the title
of "least likely to change."
Will
anything change?
Um...no.
GUY: About 10 miles outside
Atlanta, in Tucker, Georgia,
there's a 64-year-old
institution
that's
three generations strong.
And looking around,
it's pretty obvious
not too much changes
around there.
This is Matthews Cafeteria.
Hot fried chicken up!
MAN:
I would love chicken pot pie,
if you don't mind.
The best thing about Matthews
is it never changes.
Here we are.
It still hasn't changed.
It's still wonderful.
Thank you.
Well, the food is
always tremendous.
I just love it.
It was great then,
and it's great now.
GUY: That's because
owner Michael Greene
runs this place just
like his parents did,
who ran it like
their parents did.
It was your dad
that started this?
Yes.
This is
without question
one of the most unique
places we've ever been to.
To this day, we still don't
know how Triple D found us.
We were the first cafeteria
that had ever been done.
Does anybody ever do the John
Belushi and --
GREENE: Things didn't exactly
go as planned that day.
We were slated to make
sweet potato souffle.
I had already had
everything ready to go.
Guy shows up and said,
"What else can you make?"
I said,
"I can make anything."
He said,
"Biscuits and gravy."
So, that's what we did,
right on the spot.
You gonna measure that
or no?
That was
3 1/2 pounds.
17 1/2 pounds
of shortening.
Ooh!
I love
this measuring technique.
You got two spoons
right here.
Right there.
I don't know that I've
seen the man-spatula.
Mantula.
It is the mantula.
[ Chuckles ]
No rolling pin.
Just a little
patty pat.
Alright, we're just gonna
start cutting them out.
We're gonna punch them down.
There's no wrong way.
Just give
them a smack.
That is money.
That's good.
That's a biscuit.
That's when you
win with a biscuit.
That's a touchdown
right there.
And that's even before
the sausage gravy.
Nice little
pepper in there.
A little,
a little...
A lot of pepper.
That would be good
on a flip flop.
Oh man, just...
But that dough
isn't just for the biscuits.
They're also rolling it out
for a mean chicken pot pie.
Alright, first step --
chicken stock.
We're gonna go with
fresh bell pepper,
chopped onions, celery,
chicken bouillon,
black pepper,
one pound of margarine,
cream of chicken soup.
Gonna whisk
all this together.
Get this covered.
Boil for
20 or so minutes,
and then we're
gonna thicken it
with our
flour and water slurry.
Now we're going to
add mixed vegetables,
our pulled, chopped,
white-meat chicken.
Mix those
a little bit.
Now time
for the gravy,
and the part everyone loves
is the crust.
Roll it out.
Put it back
on your rolling pin,
and then just go.
You want to stretch
it a little bit.
This is
melted margarine.
It's gonna make it
really golden brown.
Our chicken pot pie
is gonna back at 350
for about an hour.
Hot chicken pot pie
up!
The chicken's shredded,
which makes it very moist,
and then the crust
is amazing.
MAN: It's kind of like
Mom use to make.
The carrots,
the green peas,
and then with the crust
and the chicken.
It's phenomenal.
GUY: And that dough
is hitting a triple --
also making a play in their
chicken and dumplings.
Now we're gonna
make dumplings?
We're gonna knead this
quite a bit
We need
a lot of it.
We need to knead it.
We need
a lot of dumplings?
We N-E-E-D a lot
of dumplings, yes.
Are we gonna
S-P-E-L-L everything?
That had
everything to do
with whether we N-E-E-D
a lot of dumplings
or whether we K-N-E-A-D
a lot of dumplings.
Both of which
is true.
O-K.
[ Both laugh ]
Alright,
here we go.
Just drop them
in in a big --
No individual --
separating them, nothing?
It's gonna
separate.
Look at that.
Okay,
time for chicken?
Yep.
Look at that,
man.       Ooh.
Come on.
Touchdown.
Wow.
If that is not
the most tender dumpling
I've ever had.
GUY: And those
chicken and dumplings
led to a match
made in heaven.
GREENE:
I met my wife.
She saw me
on "Triple D."
I came for the
chicken and dumplings,
and it's been
six years.
Married, three kids,
and now I get to eat chicken
and dumplings any time I want.
[ Laughs ]
Who's your
interior decorator?
We don't
have one.
[ Laughs ]
No.
Yes.
My father and I never saw
the need to change this place.
Will
anything change?
Um...no.
GREENE: But my wife took over
all our decorating
and she
hit a home run.
What a great place.
GREENE: Thank you.
A lot of character.
Hope you'll
come back.
Oh, you can guarantee
I'm coming back.
I love seeing
a multi-generational joint
keeping those old-school
recipes alive.
Fingers crossed
that nothing changes
when Michael's kids' kids' kids
take over.
You know what I'm saying?
But deep down in Austin...
You can call it
the Guy Fieri Tribute Sandwich.
...the winds of change
are a-blowing.
Whoo-ooh!
That's what's up.
GUY: Everything
may look different,
but the food still
reigns supreme.
GUY: It's delicious.
Congratulations.
Thank you
very much.
We'll send your
plaque in the mail.
GUY: About 20 minutes
outside of Austin, Texas,
I found this joint
that was specializing
in all things meat.
MAN: Turkey chop,
Cuban up.
GUY: But there was one
specific sandwich
that really got my attention.
[ Record scratches ]
Knuckle sandwich?
That's my line.
Wah!
Back then, they were
called Noble Pig,
and if you can't find them,
that's because they've
got a whole new location
and a whole new name.
This is
Noble Sandwich Company.
♪♪
I saw Guy on "Triple D,"
and he had a sandwich that
looked absolutely fantastic
so I just had to
come here and try it.
The sandwiches
are amazing.
Everything is
homemade from scratch.
It's just delicious.
That's thanks to owners
Brandon Martinez
and John Bates.
But you can call them the
sovereignty of sandwiches.
Is there
an association --
a world order
of Noble Pig?
[ Laughs ]
BATES: It's like
a brotherhood.
It's top-secret.
There's
a handshake and all?
There's a handshake.
[ Imitates pig snort ]
Something like that?
[ Laughs ]
GUY:
So, let's talk about
the pending lawsuit
of the Knuckle Sandwich.
Did you know that they
full-on ripped off my name?
No.
Yeah, yeah.
MARTINEZ: Guy has his company,
Knuckle Sandwich.
It's part
of his brand.
and so he really wanted to
taste a Knuckle Sandwich.
You can call it
the Guy Fieri Tribute Sandwich.
I mean,
I'm fine with that.
Alright, so this
is the knuckle.
It's a great
cut of meat.
It's very tender.
Starting off with a little
salt on this bad boy.
We go pepper on there
and then
the granulated garlic.
Pop it in the oven --
400 degrees
for about an hour
and a half or so.
Look at that.
So, we got our
knuckle meat here.
Caramelized onions
on there,
and then topping it off
with some cheddar cheese.
Got a nice ladle of
the au jus in there.
Into the oven
it goes.
And take that
whole big pile.
Just plop it right
on top of there.
Well, at least
it's not
any little petite
knuckle sandwich.
Hmm-hmm.
The meat
is cooked perfectly.
The au jus has got
real big flavor.
It's delicious.
I now recognize,
respect,
and deem this
appropriate
to be called
"Knuckle Sandwich."
Whoo!
Congratulations.
Thank you very much.
We'll send your
plaque in the mail.
GUY: While the Knuckle Sandwich
is still a knockout,
their smoked turkey chop
is also packing a punch.
Right here we have our
smoked turkey breasts.
I'm gonna add a mixture of
basil, tarragon, and parsley,
some cucumbers,
red onions,
and our lemon-coriander
vinaigrette.
Basically, it's
parsley, thyme, coriander,
lemon zest, lemon juice.
So, it's
nice and light.
We do a nice mix
on here.
Put this big pile of love
right up on top of the bread.
Whoo-ooh!
That's what's up.
Smoked turkey sandwich.
I love the turkey and the
fresh lemon and cucumber in it.
The lemon vinaigrette
made all the flavors
just really come alive.
BATES:
So, after "Triple D,"
we had to literally
move into a new location
'cause the old location
couldn't handle the business.
MARTINEZ: We ended up
switching over the name
to
Noble Sandwich Company.
Being named
"Noble Pig,"
people thought we
were just about pork,
and we got a lot
of other skills.
We do great things.
Let's offer
to a large group.
GUY: That includes
duck lovers like me.
He loved
the duck pastrami.
This is one of
our top sellers.
Oh, nice and thin.
Huh?
That's crazy.
The way he looked at it
was like a total savage.
Now what do we do?
We put a little
heat on it.
And then that's going
to get served on?
Toasted bread,
little bit
of Russian dressing.
These are
the rye pickles.
Put the lid on it,
and cut it.
♪♪
That's
darn good duck.
You guys
got to try this.
[ Imitates squishing ]
But people are also flocking
to this brand-new creation.
BATES: We added the Cuban
sandwich after "Triple D,"
and from day one,
it rocketed into our top three.
We use two different
types of house-made meats.
Slow-roasted
pulled pork,
and then we also use
our house-cured ham.
Then we add
the Swiss cheese.
We hit it with a little bit
of steam to melt the cheese.
Build the sandwich.
We start
with yellow mustard.
We put a little bit
of mayo on there.
Next up is
our homemade pickles
and then it gets topped off
with the ham, pork,
and Swiss
that we've grilled.
We add our homemade
salsa picante.
Roasted tomatoes,
cilantro, fresh onion,
pasilla chile,
ancho chile,
chile arbol -- this is
what brings the heat --
fresh-squeezed
lime juice,
distilled vinegar,
brown sugar,
garlic, salt.
[ Blender whirs ]
And it's just a touch
right across the meat.
Cuban up.
The combination
of the pulled pork and the ham
is just wonderful.
That salsa picante has a
really nice kick to it.
I love it.
GUY:
Everything you guys do --
the time you take,
the energy, the attitude --
that's what "Triple D's"
all about.
My man.
Whoo!
Yikes.
[ Laughter ]
And with two other
new locations
to go along
with that new name,
these guys are spreading the
sandwich love all over Austin.
Now, coming up...
[ Imitates
chainsaw buzzing ]
...a barbecue joint
in Salt Lake City
known for their burnt ends...
That's what heaven
looks like -- right there.
...and bringing in
the big dogs.
[ Fire truck siren wails ]
♪♪
Back in 2009, I checked out
this barbecue joint
in Salt Lake City,
where the brisket burnt ends
were so smoking...
[ Fire truck siren wails ]
...they brought out, well,
the fire department,
and from what I can
tell, it's still on fire.
This is Pat's Barbecue.
I have one
for you, sir.
Firefighters take their
food very seriously.
It is good eating.
WOMAN:
The food is delicious
and you've got Pat.
He draws everybody
in like family.
That would be owner
Pat Barber,
who got his start on
the competitive circuit.
Look at that.
That is culinary gangster
right here.
This guy rolls out.
[ Laughs ]
I couldn't have been
paid a higher compliment
because he's
a culinary gangster himself.
[ Whistles ]
Look at the size
of that brisket.
How much you gonna
trim down on that?
I'm not gonna trim
any of it.
Oh, I love it.
We're just gonna
make up a blend here.
The rub that you
use in competition?
Yes.
A product called
Butt Rub.
Butt Rub is actually a
famous barbecue team,
and this is
the goods.
Yeah.
We add a
steak seasoning to it
and add chili powder.
And then
what's this?
This is
my signature ingredient.
It's from
out of the country.
Is it always alive?
It's always alive.
Very active.
Wow.
He had no idea
what it was.
Whoa.
Ah, that's gnarly.
What is that?
We're not
gonna reveal it.
And I still
won't tell him.
Let's put it on there,
and then let it
sit overnight
'cause we want all those
spices to marry into that meat.
What kind of wood
we using?
Today,
we're using apricot.
Today
versus tomorrow?
Tomorrow,
we'll use cherry.
Where do you get it?
People's backyard.
Um...
Pat, again,
I mean,
we got to keep it down
on the culinary gangster.
You and your chainsaw
hopping fences.
[ Imitates
chainsaw buzzing]
BARBER: Let's go ahead, and
we'll put our brisket on.
GUY: What are those,
about 21-pounders?
These things
weigh about 13.
No.
That's a 17-pound
brisket if I've seen it.
He went
and grabbed a scale.
You're right.
Alright.
I mean,
I know I'm crazy
and I don't always have
both oars in the water,
but I'm just looking
at that thing
and I'm going,
"That's a monster."
[ Laughing ]
He was right.
GUY: Show me
what we got, boss.
BARBER: Okay.
You know right
where to go.
That's a cap.
That's a flat.
Now what we'll
do -- trim some of
this fat off here.
Put more
rub on here.
That's what heaven
looks like -- right there.
Look at that. Now
that's gonna go on
how much longer?
This will cook
for 10 hours.
Look at those.
Those look awesome.
I like that one.
And look at that.
Dude.
Mmm.
Is that money?
Dude, that's
cha-ching money.
[ Laughs ]
Since Guy was here last,
I am cooking
four times the amount
I used to
when I first started.
GUY:
And that includes this newcomer,
a smoked pork loin.
We're gonna start
off with our brine.
Powdered mustard,
dried rosemary,
granulated garlic,
apple cider vinegar,
black pepper,
granulated onion,
bay leaves.
Here's our
Worcestershire sauce,
kosher salt, brown sugar,
and our white sugar,
molasses.
This adds
a lot of depth to it.
We're gonna cook it
until it comes to a boil
and then I'm gonna
add ice to this.
You don't want to
add a hot brine
'cause it'll start
cooking the meat.
And then we're gonna set
it in this refrigerator
for at least two days.
I'm gonna take some
world-famous pork rub.
This cooks for
four-and-a-half hours at 225.
The pork loin will get
topped with an apple chutney.
We're gonna start off with
our Granny Smith apples,
some red bell pepper,
shallots,
raisins,
chicken stock,
brown sugar,
cinnamon,
black pepper,
kosher salt,
apple cider vinegar,
and apple whiskey.
Order up.
Pork loin
with apple chutney.
The topping on the pork
really is
a combination of flavors
that works
very, very well.
The pork loin
was so moist.
To die for.
GUY: Quality product,
good service,
and, I mean,
everybody loves the joint.
I mean, you got a herd of
firemen that come in here.
It's nuts.
It's gonzo.
It's unhooked.
It's "off the hook,"
Pat.
It's all good, Pat.
The Triple D Nation
knows what you mean
because the map of
off-the-hook places
is getting out of hand --
from Jamaica's own jerk
chicken and curry goat joint
to the between the bread
brotherhood in Austin,
walking the line at a family-run
restaurant near Atlanta...
[ Imitates electronics
warbling ]
...or sending up smoke signals
at a serious
Salt Lake City barbecue spot.
But those aren't the
only ones, folks.
Don't worry,
we got more to cover
next time
on "Triple D Nation."
GUY:
Oh, that's epic.
[ Laughter ]
This is how we shoot
"Triple D" now.
[ Laughter ]