Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Check it out.
Grab your passport
to Flavortown...
-Ahh.
-Delicious.
...'cause we're headed
all over the map.
I can't wait to see this.
From Australian favorites
in Kansas City...
Out of bounds.
...to an eclectic
El Paso eatery...
That's a Mexican pasta dish.
...and a Hawaiian
grab 'n go...
Brother.
...with funky Japanese flair.
What is this back here?
Sushi robot.
What?
Yeah.
I don't know about
this sushi robot stuff.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I've been to a lot
of restaurants,
I've been to a lot of bakeries,
but I don't think that
I've ever been
to an Australian restaurant,
and I know for a fact I've never
been to an Australian bakery.
So I'm here in Downtown Kansas
City, Missouri,
to check out just that,
an Australian bakery.
This is Banksia.
Prune and brandy pasta tart.
They have an incredible
array of food.
SERVER: Pork sandwich.
I think it's amazing
and creative.
Jerk chicken salad.
I've never been to Australia,
but when I come in here,
I feel like I have
a little taste of it.
FIERI: That's 'cause owners Rob
and Kate Joseph and Erika Vikor
are really bringing
the flavors of Down Under
to the heart of the Midwest.
How did you three
Aussies end up in KC?
I just took a dart,
threw it on the map. No.
I started a veterinary
pharmaceutical company
Bin Australia,
we moved it to the U.S.,
and after three weeks
of retirement,
my wife said I needed to get out
of the house and get a hobby.
So you opened up a bakery?
Yeah. We missed the things
that we had in Australia,
and we thought
Kansas City needed it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
MAN: Any mood you're in,
anything you need,
whether you want to grab
a pastry or a full meal.
Beef potato pie.
The beef pie is great because
the beef's really well done.
It's very savory.
It's a wonderful mix between the
meat and the mashed potatoes.
What are we
starting off with?
So we're gonna make a shortcrust
pastry for the beef pie.
We're gonna have our flour.
Just a little bit
for your homies over here?
Yeah. We'll just add a little
bit over there, so...
Well, I like to make
a lot of mess
so everyone else
can clean it up.
Just drop a little bit.
Salt.
Vinegar.
Some chilled butter.
So, we crumb that, and then
we're gonna add the water.
And we bring it all together
into a big lump.
That's a culinary term
in Australia, a "big lump."
My lovely lady lump.
Check it out.
Okay. So we have our ball
of dough that we're now --
No. Do not change it
to ball of dough.
You called it a lump.
The lump of Aussie dough.
And now we're
gonna sheet that.
Now we're gonna cut out
our rounds.
Do you normally
put flour on the ring?
Yeah.
So it doesn't do that?
You ruined that one.
There you go.
I ruined it?
I don't remember me holding the
ring without the flour on it.
Don't come to Banksia the day
after Guy's been here.
The pies will be awful.
Yeah.
Make sure that the girls
are working.
Yeah.
[ Whistles ]
So now we start forming this
into a pie tin?
We are.
We're gonna trim that up.
All right.
Now we make the filling.
Okay.
Let's do that.
We have an Angus-beef
chuck roll.
We're gonna coat that
in our spice rub.
Onion powder.
Granulated garlic.
Mustard powder.
Kosher salt.
Ginger powder.
There you go.
Celery seed.
Black pepper.
Give that a good mix.
Coat our beef in that.
And then we're gonna
brown it off with some oil.
take that liquid...
Right over the top?
Add a little bit more
of the dry mix.
Some fresh garlic.
Red onion.
Lots of red wine.
Rosemary?
Bay leaves.
And a little a bit
of cheese kofta,
so, we can pull
those out at the end.
This will go
how many hours?
Five hours at 250.
All right.
What are we into now?
Okay.
So we're gonna make
a cheesy-potato top
for this beef pie.
Okay.
Potatoes.
Half and half.
Butter.
And some water.
Water.
So after we've got these
to a softness,
we're gonna
then strain those.
We're gonna then whip them
on our big mixer
with some provolone
and some Parmesan cheese.
All right.
Let's build the pie.
So we have braised our beef.
That's some dynamite
braised beef.
And those beautiful pan
drippings that were left over...
we've made those into a gravy.
Going onto the beef...
Oh, right in there.
You bet.
And into our bases.
If you're lucky,
you'll get this one.
It's got extra.
Cheesy potatoes.
Delicious.
This then becomes our top.
Egg wash.
Poppy seeds.
In the oven about 30 minutes.
350.
And you have your beef
and red-wine pie
with cheesy-potato top.
Okay.
The braised beef inside of this
is out of bounds.
There is flavor
on top of flavor.
Great herb.
Great wine.
Fantastic texture.
Potatoes are delicious.
Love the little bit of kick
and the little bit of extra
that you're getting
from the provolone.
From the gravy to the braising
to the seasoning...
you didn't miss
an opportunity to swing.
What do you they have
in cricket?
Is it a bat?
Yep.
You didn't miss the opportunity
to swing the bat, my friend.
Delicious.
Thank you.
Beef pies
with cheesy-potato top.
This is amazing.
It's so good.
We have chicken pot pie
in the United States.
Yeah. Right.
This blows chicken pot pie
out of the water.
Oh, yeah.
It's one of my favorite
dishes here at Banksia.
FIERI;: What does the name mean,
by the way?
Banksia is a native flower
of Australia
which we have
around the restaurant,
and we needed something
that had a "B"
in it to rhyme
with "bakehouse."
Banksia Bakehouse
and Cafe.
Yeah.
Nobody can read and understand
what that word is out front.
No, I know.
We intended it that way.
No, you didn't.
But I like where you're goin'.
It's good food to match the
big personalities of the owners.
You got any other tricks
up your sleeves?
We do. We have a pork
and fennel sausage roll.
Your pork and fennel.
It's my favorite.
It was good to the last bite.
I couldn't get enough of it.
You want to see some more?
Come on back.
I'm gonna finish the pie.
And welcome
to "The Baking Hour."
I'm Guy.
And I'm Rob, the baker.
Welcome back.
"Triple D" is hanging out
in Kansas City, Missouri, at...
How do you say it?
Banks-ee-ah.
I say Banks-aya,
but it's his bakery
so we let him say
whatever he wants.
FIERI: Especially in that Aussie
accent that goes along
with his
authentic Australian menu.
Corn and zucchini
cilantro fritters.
You're not gonna find Australian
fare like this in Kansas City.
So it's pretty unique.
You're not gonna find it
in any city.
Yeah.
What do you normally get
when you come here?
The fennel and pork sausage.
ROBERT: Pork and fennel
sausage roll.
Rob's pork and fennel sausage
roll is the best I've ever had.
It just melts in your mouth.
Okay. So we're gonna make a pork
and fennel sausage roll.
Let's see it.
We're gonna make a mirepoix.
Do we turn the pot on?
Yeah, that would be...
There we go.
Yeah. Thank you.
Oil.
Red onion.
Carrot.
Celery.
Lots of garlic.
We fresh grind the fennel.
And there is plenty of it
in there.
White pepper.
Kosher salt.
Thyme.
Got it.
We are gonna cook these
for about two hours.
We're gonna caramelize them.
Okay, you said "caramel."
That's me imitating you.
Just do American for me.
[ American accent ]
So what we have here is,
we have some mirepoix
that was stuck into this pot.
We have some fennel seeds,
and we ground them fresh.
Well, now I'm going South.
Now you're going --
Black pepper.
Salt.
Thyme.
Do I sound American?
I don't know what
you sounded like.
[ Laughter ]
[ Normal voice ]
Let's do the sausage.
Pork shoulder
which we grind me.
Cooked mirepoix.
Breadcrumbs?
Yeah.
Is this from something
left over here?
It is.
Our sourdough.
We are going to roll this out
into our sausage logs.
Put all those
into the freezer.
And the puff pastry...
We use a thousand-layer
pastry technique.
I can't wait to see this.
We're gonna start
with some AP flour.
Salt. Butter.
Apple-cider vinegar.
Water.
And we're gonna make
a big dough.
Okay.
And now we're gonna sheet that,
fold that puff pastry,
and we're gonna create
1,000 layers with butter
in between so when we put it
in the oven the steam
from the butter cooking is
gonna make that pastry puff up.
Got it.
So now, frozen sausage.
We're gonna run
a little egg wash
'cause this is
kind of our glue.
Okay.
Now a little egg wash.
And then we're gonna seam it
so that it doesn't pop open.
Got it.
So, egg wash.
Sesame seed.
This is gonna get baked off
what temp?
350.
30, 35 minutes.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
You're getting this creaminess,
and this butter
and this moisture
from the puff pastry,
then you're getting
a ton of it from the pork.
All that fat that the sourdough
breadcrumbs soaked up,
plus all the mirepoix.
Copious amounts of fennel.
I mean, like, fennel city.
That's not a sausage sandwich.
No.
It's not a pig in a blanket.
It is its own entity,
and it is dynamite.
Thank you.
The pork and fennel
sausage roll.
It's moist.
And the fennel is perfect.
MAN: It's outlined
with this very flaky,
very delicious crust.
I have your lamington.
MAN: This is a great place.
Otherwise, we wouldn't come here
two or three times a week.
You'll definitely feel
like you're Down Under.
Out of control.
FIERI: Up next...
In Kauai, it's a burger joint...
A little above and beyond
what I was anticipating.
It's fresh fish...
Look at that. Ah.
...it's...
The Sushi Robot 9000!
♪♪
So I'm here on the island
of Kauai,
about 15 minutes away
from the airport,
in a little town called Kapa'a.
We're only 450 feet away
from the Saimin Dojo.
You remember those guys.
I don't know what it is about
this little town,
but they got
a food scene goin' on.
So we're here to check out
a joint where a dude
who was in Vegas
doing his food truck
met his wife, moved back
to his home-town island,
and he's all about
making Japanese comfort food.
This is Kenji Burger.
♪♪
Kenji Burger. Furikake fries.
In the window.
The food is amazing.
It never lets me down.
We were hooked from day one.
I have a Kenji Burger
and Hapa Burger ready.
The same place you can get
a grass-fed
locally raised burger
is the same place
you can get some
ahi like that.
Yeah, definitely.
FIERI: Mix in Eric Tanigawa's
Japanese heritage
and you have the quick-stop
concept that he and his wife
Whitney brought to Kauai
when they moved from Vegas.
Burgers, bowls,
and burritos.
Pretty much the one-stop shop
for Japanese comfort food.
What is this back?
Sushi robot.
What?
Yeah.
I don't know about
this sushi robot stuff.
We'll show you what it's about.
All right.
I dig it.
One sushi burrito up.
I'm up on grab 'n go.
Grab sushi burrito
and go hit the beach.
You're gonna get shrimp tempura.
You're getting the ahi poke.
A really great sauce
that's in there, as well.
It's delicious.
So everything I love
in a sushi roll
but now it's in a burrito?
Yeah.
And this is not the ahi that
you get at that grocery store.
Look at that.
That's Kauai-caught, baby.
Brother.
All right.
So give me the run down.
How does it all go?
We're gonna make
our spicy aioli.
Japanese Kewpie mayo.
Sriracha?
Chili oil.
Lemon juice.
Sashimi pepper.
And a little bit of salt.
Then, what is this setup?
This setup is gonna go
on top of the tuna
to just give it
a little bit more kick.
A little bit of sashimi pepper.
A little more sriracha.
Sesame oil.
And a little more salt.
Spicy aioli on top.
A Japanese burrito.
Absolutely.
And then we're gonna break out
the Sushi Robot 9000.
10,000.
Ohh.
It's the new edition.
Rice is already in.
Cooked sushi.
Uh-huh!
1,400 rolls an hour.
Lay the nori...
Perfect every time.
Cut our Kauai shrimp tempura.
A little surimi crab.
Okay.
Fresh ahi tuna.
Cucumber.
The spicy aioli we made earlier.
Unagi sauce.
When's it become a burrito?
Right now.
It's a seaweed tortilla.
It's ready to roll.
So what you've made
is a gigantic...
Maki roll.
...as big as a burrito.
Now I understand.
Took me a while.
I dig it.
You get the warm shrimp.
You get the cold spicy tuna.
You get the rice,
which, I'll say --
one of my big fears
of any time
I see something
being automated,
especially something
as delicate as sushi,
is that that rice
gets hammered.
It gets pressed
together too much.
I think one of the reasons
you wouldn't find people
getting sushi to go
is 'cause it takes forever.
So, what you have here,
someone can order a burger,
someone gets a fish sandwich,
and someone can get
a sushi burrito,
then you can be back
on the road in five minutes.
Right to he beach.
That's a big deal.
Well done.
Your sushi burrito.
I love the freshness
of the fish.
And the sauce is not too
overwhelming.
Just the right amount
of spiciness.
-It's really good.
-This is amazing.
This is way good.
They're brother and sister,
by the way.
They're good friends of ours.
I know their dad.
Do you eat sushi a lot?
It's my favorite food.
You're getting it like this
how fresh?
It's so fresh.
They use a lot of great
local products --
grass-fed beef, local produce...
The fresh fish comes from the
Pacific Ocean, right outside.
FIERI: Except when it doesn't.
We switch it all up, and we grab
our cod from Alaska.
Because you can't do
misoyaki cod
without having real cod
from Alaska.
The misoyaki fish burger.
Misoyaki fish burger
is my new favorite.
It literally melts
in your mouth.
A white flake fish.
Great sauce.
FIERI:
What are we into next?
We're gonna do
our misoyaki fish burger.
"Misoyaki"...
what does that mean?
It's like a miso-marinade
fish.
And you butcher it up?
We're gonna invite
Chef Charles in for that.
He's the man.
FIERI: And Head Chef Charles
Garcia Llamas has been
Eric's right-hand man
since back in the day.
-We worked together.
-In Vegas?
-In Vegas.
-Yes.
All right.
Let's get after it, Chef.
I'm just gonna flay it.
He's after it.
So he's got it
all trimmed up.
And we're gonna
use the skin on?
Yes.
We gotta keep the skin on.
Oh, I can't wait to see this.
Thank you, Chef.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Ahh.
This is the most tranquil
back kitchen/prep kitchen
I've ever been in in my life.
What are we making?
So we're gonna make our miso
marinade for our cod.
So we start off
with our saki.
Ta-da!
Hear it...
Light it up.
Wow.
Shiro miso.
Our white miso.
Sugar.
Stir it up.
Bring it to a boil.
And that's our sauce.
So, next up, we're gonna make
our amazu salad dressing.
Start with the rice vinegar.
A bunch of white sugar.
A little bit of salt.
Bring it to a boil.
Let the sugar dissolve.
Got it.
We're gonna add our kombu,
our dried seaweed.
And this is a dressing
that goes on the sandwich?
Yeah. So we take the cod right
out of the marinade,
put it into the broiler.
A lot of times, you see
a fish sandwich
and it's a fried-fish
sandwich.
Yeah.
But you're taking a premium
piece of fish,
flown in from Alaska fresh,
and you're a fast burger joint?
Yes.
Makes no sense.
This is our taro brioche bun.
Made fresh.
This taro is actually from local
farmers here in Kauai.
Okay.
This is our misoyaki cod.
Our miso sauce.
Then we're gonna go
into our salad,
with our amazu dressing
with made earlier.
And there you have it.
It's a little above and beyond
what I was anticipating.
Wow. Tender fish.
Great sauce.
You do get that nice
sweet of the miso,
and then you get
the sour of the vinegar
and you get that little play
going back and forth.
Brioche bun.
Is this a local bakery?
Yes, it is.
The bun that they are
making you is rockin'.
When you're gonna come
to the islands
and you're going to enjoy
a fish sandwich,
the last thing you want
is to have it fried.
Exactly.
Nicely done.
-Thank you.
-You're misoyaki fish sandwich.
Misoyaki fish burger is amazing.
With the misoyaki sauce?
It's a perfect example of Eric's
Japanese and Hawaiian fusion.
Beautifully done.
I just like the combination
of flavors.
It works really well.
-You gonna come back?
-For sure.
One Happa Burger in the window.
It's unlike any other place
in Kauai.
Very, very delicious.
FIERI: Thoughtful, mindful menu
done the right way,
with the discipline...
You got it goin', man.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
Coming up...
A funky international spot
in El Paso...
Outstanding.
...mashin' up Mexican
with Italian...
I think you made yourself a dish
that is a one-of-a-kind.
...a taking the tostada
into new territory.
This is a postcard
from Flavortown, man.
♪♪
So I'm here on the lower west
side of El Paso, Texas,
where a chef has taken
an old franchise burger joint
and turned it into a restaurant
where he's serving up...
they call it "cuisine el truco,"
which, in my bad
Spanish translation,
will mean
the "cuisine of El Paso."
This is Rulis'.
♪♪
Champ Burger ready.
Rulis' is one of the
great restaurants in El Paso.
I need pico.
WOMAN: The ability the chef
has to just create something
completely different...
it's just something
that I applaud him for.
FIERI: The props go
to Rulis Gonzalez,
who owns this joint
with his dad, Raul.
And the local flavors
he's reppin'
are actually pretty global.
When you describe
the food of El Paso --
I assume it's a lot
of Mexican food,
but are there
other cultures?
Native Americans
were here first.
The Spanish came through.
Chinese built the railroads.
Middle Eastern entrepreneurs.
Is that pita ready?
This restaurants is known
as an international kitchen
because it has
a mix of flavors.
It's a gourmet dive.
You're gonna get a variety
of everything.
-What do you think of the pasta?
-Very good, sir.
Pasta Chihuahua.
The Pasta Chihuahua
has some chorizo in it.
It's Chihuahua,
the state that I'm from.
It just reminds me
of the amazing flavors
that I had
when I was a child.
FIERI:
We're making pasta Chihuahua?
It's a take on a Bolognese.
Okay.
But we're gonna use
Mexican chorizo.
That is the biggest log of
Mexican chorizo I've ever seen.
Everything's bigger
in Texas.
Onions. Garlic.
Blessed be.
Ro-Tel with green chili.
Fresh tomato.
Cumin.
Oregano.
Spicy sausage link.
And last but not least,
the chicken stock.
And next?
Grilled steak.
Just what I thought.
When I normally have my
Bolognese El Paso Mexican style,
I put a steak on it.
Got to.
Good talk.
This is our house seasoning.
Salt. Paprika.
Granulated garlic.
And black pepper.
Onto the skirt steak.
We're gonna put a sear on it.
Sear-iously?
[ Crickets chirping ]
Buh-dum-bum!
I'll be here all week.
A nice, big chunk.
We've had long and chunky here
so far, folks.
Throw a little bit of water
in the pan.
Okay.
Pasta goin' in.
Add our steak.
Our meat sauce.
All right.
Some Cotija cheese.
A little cilantro from our herb
garden out front.
And there you go.
Here's our pasta Chihuahua.
In this, no Chihuahuas
were harmed.
[ Laughs ]
That's a Mexican
pasta dish.
Indeed.
The meat, the way
you season it...
it's super tender.
It is one interesting dish.
I'm trying to put
my finger on it.
I think it's the tomatoes...
with the green chili...
with the Cotija...
with the other
great ingredients.
I think you made yourself a dish
that is a one-of-a-kind.
I don't think you'll find that
in many restaurants.
I don't think so either.
Well done.
Thank you.
I got a pasta Chihuahua
at the window.
The pasta Chihuahua
is delicious.
Very hearty.
Very savory.
The spiciness with
the combination
of the queso fresco
is amazing.
Walkin' in.
Spinach pizza.
The chef really puts
a lot of effort
into sourcing quality
local ingredients.
Recently, the Department
of Agriculture in New Mexico
started spending a lot of money
for young people
to get back into the fields.
I started working with some
of the local farmers
about seven years ago.
Grilled veggie flat bread.
At the window.
The food is very eclectic.
The oxtail tostadas.
The oxtail tostada is amazing.
It has a creamy bean layer
and the smoky oxtail.
The meat just kinda melts
in your mouth.
What is next
on the game plan?
Now we're gonna make some oxtail
for our tostadas.
Okay. Same seasoning we used
on the skirt steak?
Yeah.
So we're gonna sear those off.
Okay, Chef.
Take these out.
Okay.
Carrot.
Celery. Onions.
Garlic.
Our mirepoix.
Bits and chunks in there.
Bits and Chunks.
One of my favorite bands.
Bits 'n chunks,
bits 'n chunks
So two poblanos
and the jalapeño. Got it.
Jalapeño.
Coriander seed.
Cumin. Pepper.
And a bay leaf.
This is gonna braise
for eight hours.
Bring it out, let it cool,
pull it.
Next for this tostada is?
We're gonna do
the bean purée.
Beef fat. Onion.
Garlic.
And what beans
are we using?
That's frijoles de charro.
That's what I thought
they were.
Right across the border...
that's where we get those beans.
Put the water in now.
So we'll let these go for a
simmer for about two hours?
For about two hours.
Mm-hmm.
We'll add the salt
and the cumin,
and then we're gonna
purée those.
What else is going on
this dish?
There's a salsa verde.
Onion. Poblanos.
Jalapeños.
Garlic.
We throw it in the wood oven.
You get a nice char on there.
Water. Cilantro.
Some lime juice.
Ready to go.
Bean purée down.
Salsa verde.
Shredded lettuce.
Oxtail is ready.
Pico de gallo with avocado...
pickled cabbage...
I love tostadas, but they always
explode on me.
[ Laughs ]
Don't laugh.
♪♪
Crunchy tortilla.
Bean purée.
Nice hint from
the salsa verde.
This is a postcard
from Flavortown, man.
The fresh pico
mixed with the avocado
with that creaminess
all covering and supporting
and balancing
the unctuousness of this oxtail
which is so creamy
and tender.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
Oxtail tostadas.
You can taste everything
from the top to the bottom.
An explosion of flavor
in your mouth.
Show me the technique
of eating the tostada.
[ Laughs ]
Ah-ha-ha. Ah-ha-ha.
Ah-ha-ha-ha.
Really.
You're gonna crack it.
Ah.
A lot of finesse there.
Chicken Calabacitas. Up.
This is home for us,
and we love it.
Eclectic menu,
but delivers.
Well done.
Thank you.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry.
There's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
Out of all the karaoke songs
that you do...
Yeah.
...what is your best?
♪ Goin' down in a blaze
of glory ♪
Oh, my gosh!
I gotta get front-row tickets!