Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, yeah.
All day.
Yay!
...we're cruising the country...
You can't have that
and not smile.
...on a worldwide
flavor adventure...
That's a passport
to Flavortown right there.
...like rock-star-run Polynesian
in Kauai...
It's show biz.
FIERI: ...legit Lebanese
in San Diego...
That's slamma-jamma lamb-a.
...and a Delaware deli...
Look at that bite right there.
...spanning the globe
from Thailand to Cuba.
That is how you're supposed
to make a Cubano.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
Love coming to the Hawaiian
islands for "Triple-D" --
funky joints,
great people,
and one of my favorites
is the rockers' restaurants.
Remember Sammy Hagar and I
went to
Mick Fleetwood's
place over in Maui?
Off the hook.
Well, then you guys
all write in and say,
"Listen, you got to check
this joint out
next time you go to Kauai."
It's owned by Todd Rundgren --
you know, the rocker --
and his wife, Michele.
This is it -- Tiki Iniki.
♪♪
One Iniki Burger, on the grill.
It's a real, traditional, 1950s,
Trader Vic-emulating tiki bar.
Here's our Shrimp Rangoons.
-We come here a lot.
-Real deal?
Real deal.
FIERI: And the same attitude
real-deal rockers
Todd and Michele Rundgren
brought to their music
goes into every inch
of this joint.
The band I was in,
The Tubes, we just --
Right. Love The Tubes.
We went crazy.
I thought, "I'm gonna get
a little bit
of that rock-star-ism
back in here."
So we get wacky.
Yay!
How long you guys been open?
Five years.
Oh, it's got so much funk
and character to it,
I thought it had been here
50 years.
50 years' worth of funk
in a 5-year package.
FIERI:
And to drum up a funky menu,
they pulled friend and chef
Mike Moore up on stage.
We've gone to his barbecues
on the beach forever,
and we knew
Chef Mike had to be our chef.
One Fish & Chips.
The food is excellent here.
The Sweet Sticky Ribs
are my favorite.
Sweet Sticky Ribs.
Pick it up.
They're unbelievable.
They're, like, five-napkin ribs.
-What are we gonna make?
-Sticky Sweet Ribs.
We're gonna put together
a simmering liquid.
Start with the water,
our soy sauce,
and use the local kind of soy,
the Aloha soy.
Not too salty,
not too heavy.
Black pepper, bay leaves.
-Garlic.
-Chopped ginger.
And a bunch of brown sugar.
We'll put this over the ribs.
Wrap her up. So, they're
gonna get the steam.
They're gonna get the braise.
Pop them in the oven,
350 for about 5 hours.
Alright, Chef,
what are we into?
Guava glaze -- lime juice.
Got it.
Our guava puree, aji-mirin,
sweet cooking wine...
The sweet cooking wine.
Got it.
...our Aloha soy,
and some honey.
Boil and then simmer it
for a little bit
to get the flavors together.
Tighten it with a little
cornstarch slurry.
When the ribs come out,
hit them on the grill.
Give them a little mark.
Put them in the sauce.
I like it.
Don't be shy with the sauce,
Chef.
Throw a little
green onion curls on that.
-Okay.
-And there you go.
It is about 9,000 degrees.
I can see it.
Yeah.
That's delicious.
Hawaii loves everything that
you put on this plate.
Some sticky rice --
it's a nice touch.
You're making kalua pork
in the pan,
but keeping it on the bone
and giving it all that crust.
It's a great rib meat,
which everybody loves.
And then that little
charred crunch
that you get from
the grill and the candy.
You can't have that
and not smile.
Sticky Sweet Ribs.
-MAN: Alright.
-Amazing. Amazing flavor.
Super awesome sauce.
WOMAN: Take one bite, and it's,
like, melting.
And that's what I want in a rib.
So, how do you describe
the place to people?
Well, I'm a tiki-phile.
So, you're a freaky
of the tiki?
I'm a freaky of the tiki.
It's one of my favorite tiki
joints on my favorite island.
Are we a real tiki roof
and we have to come
and change out the palms and --
Yep.
You forget the ordinary life
and everything is wild and crazy
and you can just
let yourself go.
They've got these great wigs
that look like birthday cakes.
By the way, if you could
take a look at my crew.
[ Michele laughs ]
They're definitely in
the spirit of the event.
WOMAN: This is where
the community is.
We gather together
and we drink and we eat.
One Iniki Burger in the window.
Pick it up.
The Iniki Burger is
a SPAM burger, basically.
It's like my childhood
all over again.
This was a concept
of Todd's and Michele's.
-Okay.
-SPAM.
Well, I have a blocker
on my compu-- Oh.
This SPAM.
[ Laughs ]
Dice that.
Throw it in the frying pan.
Gives it a little texture.
Pulls a little bit
of the salt out.
-Yeah.
-Now into the 80-20.
We're gonna form these
into patties.
And then some pickled
vegetable on top.
-Do you make that also?
-Yes, we do.
You're an underachiever.
We're gonna start with our
rice wine vinegar, water...
A whole bunch of sugar.
...fresh ground garlic...
Salt.
...and a little bay leaf.
Just bring it to a boil.
Shredded carrots.
Red onions.
And thin-sliced jalapeño.
And let it steep.
This goes for about 24 hours
before you use it?
Yeah. Slaw goes on
the bottom of the burger,
mayonnaise, fresh thyme.
That's a lot of thyme.
I like that thyme flavor.
Evidently.
Fresh garlic, white pepper.
I've seen a lot of dressings --
never that much thyme.
Grated carrots, Napa cabbage,
and some radish sprouts.
Little bit of the dressing.
Doctor.
We're good to go.
-Yes, sir.
-So, let's get a burger down.
Top that burger
with our onion compote...
You're an animal.
...and provolone cheese.
Hit that with a little steam.
Soy mayo.
Okay.
Slaw dressing on the bottom.
And once that's done,
on top of that...
Pickled carrots and jalapeños
and onions.
Yeah.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
This is not a,
"Throw SPAM on there,
and all the tourists
will like it."
It's really unique.
You got a lot going on
in there, buddy.
Caramelized onions
are great.
The pickled veggies on top
are probably my favorite.
Nice bun.
When you're going to make
that one of the lead songs
of the concert,
you better pull it off.
And you did.
People got to dig it.
Great.
Delicious burger.
I mean, really.
I have your Iniki Burger.
That SPAM inside of it
gives it a charm
that's very typical
of the islands.
Tiki Iniki has the rep
with the locals.
Yes.
It's not just a, if you're a fan
of Todd and Michele
you're a fan of the music...
No. No.
You're coming here
because you dig the food.
And the atmosphere.
And the bar.
Tiki Iniki rocks!
Just a wonderful place.
FIERI: There's a difference
between a celebrity
putting their name on it
and really owning it, loving it,
and making it
their pride and joy.
It's show biz.
It was supposed to be a music
venue with good food,
and it turned out to be great
food and music in the courtyard.
I appreciate you inviting us.
This is really --
-I'm glad that you're here.
-Thanks for swimming over.
FIERI: Up next,
in Wilmington, Delaware...
This guy doesn't stop.
...a chef stuffing
the whole world...
There is no question
this is Thai curry.
...into serious
sausage sandwiches.
Wow. That's good.
♪♪
So, I'm here on the south side
of Wilmington, Delaware,
and, you know, I'll tell you,
"Triple D" doesn't get out
to Delaware enough
'cause this food scene
is going on.
I'm here to check out a joint
where a culinary instructor,
all in one year,
decides to buy a house,
have a baby,
and open up a sausage emporium.
This is Maiale.
♪♪
Table 62, sausage and peppers.
The food at Maiale is fantastic.
The sausages, the salami,
the prosciutto.
Walking in -- Corned Beef
Reuben and Short Rib.
His sausages are unique,
flavorful,
hit the spot every single time.
FIERI: And when it comes
to making the sausage,
Chef Billy Rawstrom's
big on the pig
and then goes even
bigger from there.
BILLY: "Maiale" is
Italian for "pig."
Majority of our stuff
is from the pig.
What were you doing
before you did this?
I taught culinary arts,
wanted to work for myself,
so I thought,
"How can I use my chef skills
to make something
that's gonna be different?"
Got it. And how many different
sausages do you make?
Up to 40.
I thought, "What foods
do I like?"
Right.
"And how do I make that
into a sausage?"
"How do I make a pepperoni pizza
and chicken sausage?"
So I did that.
So, you just do
whatever you want.
Pretty much.
He blends different flavors
together that you might not
ever think would belong
in sausage, but it's delicious.
Walking in -- Thai Curry.
WOMAN:
The Thai Curry chicken sausage
is one of my
favorite sandwiches.
It's got a great amount
of spice.
The curry --
it blasts in your mouth.
Alright, well,
let's get after it.
What are we making?
Alright, so, today we're
gonna do the Thai Curry
chicken sausage.
Here I have our ground
chicken thighs.
-You bringing this in ground?
-No.
-We grind it ourselves.
-Okay.
Yeah, my grinder's, like, a --
Show-off.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
Then we have some ground
pork fat, garlic,
chopped cilantro,
cayenne pepper, curry powder...
You're getting after it.
...a little white pepper,
salt.
Finish it with lime juice
and then coconut milk.
Everything you'd like
in a nice Thai meatball.
-Whoa.
-I know.
I have seen some big
sausage stuffers.
That right there might
take the cake.
This is actually
our smaller one.
I have one that's
double this size.
This is sexy.
Synthetic casing or natural?
No, we do all-natural
hog casings.
Got it.
So, now that the links are made,
we're gonna poke
any air gaps out of there.
I only want to poke
where the holes are.
Right.
I don't just want to kind of go
willy-nilly at it.
You don't want to get
all willy-nilly
when you're making
your sausage.
Put them on the water
to poach.
And then for service...
We'll slice them and put them
on the grill.
Now we're making
our Asian slaw --
shredded red cabbage,
shredded carrots,
kosher salt, sugar, garlic,
soy sauce, lime juice,
and sesame oil at the end.
Dig it.
Where's the bun coming from?
We get our buns
out of Jersey --
nice and firm,
crispy on the outside.
Get a nice toasty toast
on that.
Did he say "toasty toast"?
Take some of our slaw,
pop it on top.
Asian sriracha mayo.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
Chef, I'll tell you what.
You'd be hard-pressed
to tell somebody
that didn't come out of a famous
Thai restaurant.
There's good heat.
There's good curry.
There's nice balance
with this crunch.
The sausage is super moist.
When you call it Thai curry,
you want it to be Thai curry.
You don't want the aioli
to be carrying the curry flavor.
There is no question this is
Thai curry.
♪♪
That's real deal.
Thank you.
You should think about
taking up this sausage thing.
I know it's a long shot.
[ Laughs ]
Well done.
Thai chicken curry sandwich.
Thank you.
The slaw is crisp.
The aioli is delicious.
The bread is perfect.
You don't want that last bite.
You want more and more.
Roman Chicken sausage.
Basil mayo.
Billy's just phenomenal.
He's the Sausage King
of Delaware.
FIERI: And he's certainly
putting plenty on his plate.
So, let me count this down --
the restaurant, the one child,
the two child,
the wife, the house,
and a food truck,
and the farmers' market.
And the warehouse
where we do USDA.
And he does our catering
for our barbecues in the summer.
Yeah, he caters
our barbecues.
Tuck your cape in and fly
over there.
This guy doesn't stop.
And Billy's not just
slingin' bangin' brats.
WOMAN: He's really creative
in the kitchen.
There's always new flavors.
Out of everything on the menu,
what's your favorite?
The Castro sandwich,
the Cuban sandwich.
Oh, the Castro --
it's like getting on a plane
and flying to Cuba.
It starts with the pork,
and that's Billy's specialty,
accompanied by Swiss cheese
and ham.
It's just wonderful.
So, we do our own ham
for what we call The Castro.
Let's get after that.
We're gonna make
the brine for it.
Start with cold water,
kosher salt, sugar, curing salt.
We like to give it a little
acid with the lemon
and a few bay leaves.
We'll stir it up,
bring it to a simmer
for about 10 minutes,
cool it down.
And how long
we gonna brine this?
Seven days.
Alright, so, now we got our ham,
boned, rolled, tied.
We're gonna make
our glaze for it.
Brown mustard,
molasses, and garlic.
From here, we'll go in an oven.
275 for...
About an hour and a half.
Next up?
We have a picnic shoulder here
for our pulled pork
for the sandwich.
Got it.
Picnic shoulder being
the bottom of the shoulder.
It definitely has a lot
of marbling,
definitely has
a lot of flavor.
Some salt, sugar, paprika,
oregano, chili powder,
granulated garlic,
and black pepper.
Mix it up.
Take our flap,
get underneath there.
Are we gonna let this marinate
at all before we go or --
Yeah, if you could let it go
for a day, that's great.
Then we'll add our cold water.
And then we do a two-part cover
and put it in the oven.
250, 8 to 12 hours.
Now we're gonna pull the pork.
Okay. Get it done.
Now that our ham is cooked,
we're gonna slice it up.
That's what I'm talking about.
Just like Christmas ham
right there, folks.
Mmm.
A little sweet
from that molasses.
Oh, that's delicious.
So, now we're gonna build
the sandwich.
Add a little
garlic-infused oil.
It's gonna go right
on this ciabatta bread.
We do our pork, do our ham,
let that get a good sear.
We'll top it with the pickles
and the cheese all melty-melty.
That was "melty-melty"
you just dropped me.
I just dropped that on you.
Okay.
It's gonna be molten lava.
Look at that bite
right there.
♪♪
Wow, that's good.
I mean, that is everything
you want a Cubano to be.
The pork's got a great texture.
The bread is perfect.
The Dijonnaise is right
on point,
enough of the Swiss,
and the pickles shining through.
That is how you're supposed
to make a Cubano.
Who makes the pickles?
We make the pickles here.
Who grew the mustard?
-Uh...
-Underachiever!
[ Laughs ]
Selling a Castro, number 85.
The pork is crispy.
The mustard is spicy.
The ham really makes it.
Pop of tangy with the pickles.
Really delicious.
BILLY: I need kraut to finish
the Reubens.
MAN: I love this place.
I can't imagine not having this
in Wilmington.
You know what you're doing.
You got a really good hand
at spice,
how to do it in balance,
how to build flavor.
Thanks, Chef.
Excellent.
And I'll take 6 pounds of ham,
14 pounds of salami.
Let me get some of
the Thai sausages.
I want to try that
pepperoni one also.
Can I also get some pickles?
♪♪
Coming up, an authentic
Lebanese joint in San Diego...
Hey, we're partying.
...putting fantastic flavor
on flatbread...
I could have 100 of those.
...and a lamb dish gone wild.
It's taking everything I have
to not completely devour
that entire plate.
Look at that bite right there.
[ Mouth full ] Oh, my God,
is that hot. Really hot.
That was really hot. Hot!
A little hot.
♪♪
So, I'm here in San Diego,
down the street
from San Diego State University,
and there is something
about restaurants
in these college areas.
Maybe it's because
college kids --
well, they'll try anything,
and they love ethnic food.
Maybe it's 'cause
they're eating on a budget.
They got to find a good deal.
And one of the things is,
they are brutally honest.
Either they love it,
or they don't.
So, when I hear there's a joint
that everybody's digging
and it's Lebanese,
I'm checking it.
This is Alforon.
♪♪
Chicken with everything,
spinach and cheese.
The food is just amazing.
I'm transported to Lebanon.
They're almost done.
The different types of spices
and combinations of them --
it's a constant surprise
in your mouth.
FIERI:
And it's no wonder it's all
cooked up by George Salameh
because Lebanese grub
is in his blood.
The credit really goes
to my dad.
-He was a master chef.
-Where?
In the old country, in Lebanon.
I wanted to go do
my own thing.
I was an airline pilot
for six years.
For 6 or 60?
6. No, not 60.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe you're a vampire.
Maybe you're like
148 years old.
If I am that,
you'll be 1,048.
[ Laughing ]
Two soujouk coming out.
I work all over the county,
but I will come to Alforon
just to have Lebanese food.
-And the name means...
-"The oven."
WOMAN:
They have the oven here,
and this oven
makes beautiful flatbreads.
Here's your soujouk.
The soujouk flatbread --
it has ground meat
mixed with spices
and cheese on top.
It's just amazing.
What are we making?
So, we're making the soujouk.
Soujouk.
Uh-huh.
We're gonna cook the meat.
We'll use the smasher.
The smasher.
Some oil here, onions.
Why are we cooking the meat
and the onions separate?
Well, that's how --
That's how you learned it.
That's how I used to do it.
Some salt.
Tomatoes.
Black pepper, cayenne pepper,
lemon in here.
A bunch of garlic.
Soujouk spices.
Soujouk, as in...
It's got cumin, fenugreek.
It's got allspice, cinnamon,
sumac, paprika.
We import it
from the old country.
It's delicious.
Thank you.
The soujouk.
Ahh.
We're gonna combine
those together.
Alright,
let's make this dough.
Unbleached flour, oil,
fresh yeast, salt, sugar,
and some water.
Got it.
It's gonna mix for about
10 minutes.
Place it on this tray
and cut it.
So, we're gonna flour this
a little bit.
We sheet them
as we need to order.
Sheet 'em as you need 'em.
Now the meat has cooled down,
and we're gonna put it
on a flatbread, top it
with white Lebanese cheese.
What temp are the ovens
running at?
490 to 500 degrees.
Cook it for about
2 to 3 minutes.
♪♪
I could have 100 of those.
You could also throw an egg
in there.
We were just talking
about nice things,
having a fun time, and then,
"Put an egg on it."
I don't like eggs.
That's why we don't
present it...
[ Laughs ]
That's a passport
to Flavortown right there.
Great spice, great texture
of the crust,
not pizza crust.
Definitely light and crispy
and thin like flatbread,
a touch of the cheese,
a strong ethnic flavor.
Delicious.
Really nice.
Soujouk, middle table.
So, the soujouk flatbread
is really good
because that meat has
a little bit of a spice.
It's really nice with tomatoes.
The Lebanese cheese
is very light,
and it melts inside your mouth.
Two chicken ready.
So, this is my buddy P.T. here.
You serve our country.
Thank you.
You've traveled the world.
Ever had Lebanese food?
Yeah.
Actually, I have been in Lebanon
having Lebanese food.
So, kind of showing off now.
It's my "Triple D,"
and all of a sudden it's
"P.T.'s Cultural
Food Experiences."
[ Laughs ]
Thanks for joining us.
This here brings me
right back to that.
Just the ingredients
that he uses -- it's delicious.
Lebanese food
has its own, like, style.
It's its own thing.
It's so many different spices
that it's hard to describe it.
MAN:
They've traded with everybody
throughout the world,
and so it's an amalgamation
of many different flavors.
What'd I get, a history
teacher for the interview?
-[ Woman laughs ]
-Vegan Kibbie.
What else are
we gonna do, Chef?
We're gonna do the lamb --
Well, don't tell me.
Don't tell me.
But here's a hint.
Ouzi Lamb.
I have had the Ouzi Lamb
over 70 times.
It's such a special dish.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
So, welcome back.
We're hanging out at Alforon
in San Diego, California.
I've lived for 25 years
in Lebanon,
and this is the only
authentic Lebanese place
that I've been to
in San Diego.
FIERI: And that authenticity
comes from George Salameh,
who's dishing out
the flavors of his homeland.
-Ouzi Lamb.
-The Ouzi Lamb is just amazing.
It's really tender.
WOMAN:
It's a long-grain rice.
You put the yogurt on top of it.
WOMAN: I asked George,
"Where do you buy your yogurt?"
He's like, "Buy? I make every
single thing from scratch."
-Ouzi Lamb.
-Ouzi Lamb with Ouzi Rice.
So, we have a de-boned
leg of lamb.
We're gonna add
a little bit of oil.
We're gonna sear it.
Right in the pot.
Take them out.
Apple cider vinegar.
And then we're gonna get oil,
garlic, onion, cook these down.
Next step?
Sherry cooking wine,
Marsala wine, and Burgundy wine.
-Some salt.
-There you go.
Cinnamon, black pepper,
allspice.
A little allspice there.
Got it.
Water in there.
What is our little sachet?
This one has bay leaf
and it has dried rosemary
that we're gonna
throw inside here.
We're also gonna put
tomatoes in there.
Fresh garlic.
And braise this off
for how long?
For 3 1/2 to 4 hours,
about 450, 500 degrees.
Covered or not?
Covered.
Next we're gonna do
the seasoned rice.
Oil in here, onions.
Ground beef.
And we're gonna add the rice.
Basmati rice.
Basmati. Okay.
Water?
Correct.
Black pepper, salt.
Doctor.
Cinnamon.
And some allspice.
The rice is gonna cook.
We gonna make the yogurt sauce?
Yeah, we sure can.
-Let's make it.
-Yeah.
Hey, we're partying.
Whole milk -- boil it.
And then we're gonna let it
cool to about 107
to 110 degree Fahrenheit.
That's where I usually
keep mine.
When it cools down,
we add the culture to it.
This is yogurt
that we've made.
Every time you make it,
you scoop some for the homies.
-Exactly.
-We want the funk.
♪ Oh, we want the funk ♪
♪ Funk ♪
Keep it warm about seven
to eight hours.
That's yogurt.
Okay, Chef, let's see it.
Rice.
These pieces on top.
Oh, so this isn't
a one-plater.
You're sharing this
with the family.
That's right.
The roasted nuts.
Yogurt.
That's it.
That's how we do it.
♪♪
It's taking everything
I have to not
completely devour
that entire plate.
The rice of course
is delicious.
But the lamb is cooked down
just enough,
and that little acidic touch
with the onions
and the garlic...
pairs with that lamb
perfectly.
The nuts,
that textual difference,
add a nice,
much-needed component.
And the cool yogurt playing
with the rice, the ground beef,
the onions, and the lamb --
that's slamma-jamma lamb-a.
Wash it down with just
a little bit of yogurt.
I'm gonna wash that down
and put it in my pocket.
But I got to go get
some bigger pants
'cause I got to steal a lot
of that soujouk, too.
I got a lot
that I'm gonna be taking.
Why don't you go look around
for a bit?
Yeah.
I want to see what else
I can rip off.
Well done, my friend.
Well done.
Thank you.
Ouzi Lamb.
it's insane.
It's so good.
The yogurt gives it a little bit
of a tangy taste.
The spices are the real spices
that I remember from Lebanon.
Portobello mushroom!
I found this place
about two months ago,
and I've been here
a dozen times.
That's 60 days,
and you've only been 12 times?
-I know.
-I'm a little disappointed.
The owners are really friendly
and warm and welcoming.
It's one of the best restaurants
I've ever been to.
Delicious food, great culture,
great energy.
Awesome.
So, was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I just got hired
yesterday, man.
I have no clue
what I'm doing here.
Hey, listen.
Neither of us do.
Just keep it quiet, alright?
Just, uh, fake it till you
make it.
[ Laughing ]