Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown!
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
This trip...
I'm gonna release the jaw.
...we're going crazy
with chicken
and getting twisted
with burgers.
I do not know what's going on
in this kitchen.
Like banging recipes
in a Vancouver hidden gem.
When we talk about
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives",
you take the dive award.
Bird in a bun and mushroom
mania in San Diego...
I'm trying really hard
not to eat the whole thing.
...plus snappy skins
in Delaware...
That's a real good chicken skin.
...alongside beef
bacon burger bomb.
It's gonna get messy, folks.
I do this for you.
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
♪♪
So, I'm here on Market Street
in downtown
Wilmington, Delaware,
right down the street from
the riverfront.
Now, I'm here to check out
a joint where three buddies
were tasting some bourbon
and they decided they're gonna
open up a restaurant.
Oh, they had
some fantastic names.
Let's see, the first one
was Salad Burger,
then they had Drunken Cow,
and then after tasting
a little bit more bourbon,
they came up with it.
This is the Farmer & The Cow.
♪♪
Pick up, please.
I come here, number one,
for the great food.
It's outstanding.
Oh, my God.
You can make a lot of decisions
you'll regret
at the gym the next day.
That's a great way to say it.
Great beer selection,
great bourbon selection.
FIERI: Which are two of
the cravings
that brought Mike Day,
Jasper Singh, and Matt Collins
together
when they opened this joint,
and to make it a triple play...
What's the big claim
to fame on the menu?
Our burgers.
We bring in all the meat
ourselves, we grind everything.
FIERI: With Chef Jasper as
the unlikely meat master.
Who's the vegetarian chef?
Me.
I should have picked that up.
Yeah, that was easy, right?
Yeah.
That guy doesn't say
fresh greens.
I said burgers.
Thank you.
Yeah.
In first, That'll Do, Pig.
The That'll Do, Pig burger
has got layers
and layers of bacon --
bacon jam.
It's insane.
-Why do we call this...
That'll Do, Pig?
Because my partner, Mike,
is a big fat pig
sometimes and he likes to eat.
O.M.G.
He's in good shape, but he loves
to eat a lot of crazy things.
We're actually gonna start
grinding brisket...
-Short rib...
-Chuck...
-And then the filet.
-Yep.
Divide this in half and then
you regrind half of it.
This is a method
I have not seen before.
So, now what are we making?
Our Bacon Giant.
Bacon, some onions in there,
reserved bacon fat, soy sauce,
cold coffee,
Worcestershire sauce, hoisin.
This is 97 ingredients.
It is.
Molasses, gochujang.
That's it, I'm leaving.
Apple cider vinegar.
Wing of bat, eye of newt.
Ketchup, brown sugar.
Put some sumac in there
and I'm walking.
You might want to start walking.
Sumac is this great Indian
spice, a little lemony hit.
Onion powder, allspice, cumin,
paprika, garlic powder,
cayenne, lemon pepper,
salt and pepper.
It's a half-hour show, please.
I apologize, I apologize.
We just got white sugar,
chili powder.
All right, how long
is this gonna cook down?
About two hours,
really low heat.
So let it sit overnight
before we serve it.
What else we got?
We're gonna start
making our cart sauce.
Onions, olive oil,
molasses, soy sauce,
Worcestershire sauce,
cayenne, brown sugar,
chili powder, mustard powder,
salt and pepper, ketchup.
It cooks for about half an hour
to 45 minutes.
And next we make the burger.
We'll start with our salt
and pepper rub,
horse radish cheddar,
house-cut bacon,
then we're gonna add
our cart sauce,
the bacon jam we made...
Good fry right there.
Add our burger on top,
bacon mayo,
and, of course,
the best part, tater tots.
This'll be interesting.
It's gonna get messy, folks.
I do this for you.
You have a beach towel?
You should have called it
the farmer and the pig
after that one.
Dynamite though.
The bacon jam screams.
♪♪
The cart sauce
really carries it through.
Yeah.
You're hitting all
the critical points.
You have the crunch,
you have the acid,
you have the texture,
you have the seer.
Excellent.
Thanks, man.
That'll Do, Pig for you.
That'll Do, Pig.
Thanks a lot.
That's just enough out of you,
as well.
It's delicious.
Very thick, very juicy.
The bacon jam is kind of
the star of it.
Put that on anything
and it'd be great.
Bacon jam mac and cheese
pick up, please.
Great restaurant, great bar,
as well.
They do have one of the most
distinctive bourbon selections
in the area.
How many bourbons do you have?
About 170.
And how many have you tried?
170.
Just sips.
Just little sips.
Oh, yeah.
Four burgers ready.
The burgers are amazing,
all the apps are delicious.
Chicken skins up for 31!
The chicken skins
are really good.
Whoa!
Basically the best part
of fried chicken.
Have that Nashville kind
of hot chicken spice to it.
What are we into?
Fried chicken skins
with Nashville hot rub.
So, chicken chicharrones.
We're just gonna start by
putting some olive oil down,
laying them out so all the fat
can render off of them.
In the oven,
15 minutes, 350°.
Absolutely.
What's up next?
So, we're gonna make
the Nashville dry rub.
I only know Nashville
to be cayenne.
We maybe take a little liberty
with it.
Brown sugar, salt and pepper...
Cayenne...
Chili powder, cumin,
mustard powder,
paprika, coriander,
lemon pepper.
We left Nashville
a long time ago.
Onion powder, garlic powder,
Carolina reaper powder.
Fantastic.
Next up?
Homemade ranch.
Okay.
Mayonnaise, sour cream,
white pepper...
All right.
...salt, turmeric...
Yellow ranch.
Sage, granulated onion,
granulated, garlic, parsley,
chives, dried dill,
now fresh dill, and just
a little bit of lemon juice.
Okay.
And then we slowly
add our buttermilk.
And this will, of course,
get better with time.
Absolutely.
We won't serve this
until at least 24 hours.
All right,
fry these things.
Some of our Nashville dry rub.
That's a real good
chicken skin.
I love that crunch.
Got a little bit of heat,
got a little bit of sweet,
got a touch of salt.
The 97-ingredient ranch
dressing, also very good.
And I think your execution
is spot on.
I'm gonna have a nice flight
of bourbon,
have these kind
of refreshes the palate.
Whatever you're making
could benefit
from a little crispy
fried chicken skin.
I want a side of those
on any burger I order.
You chicken skins.
Thank you.
Definitely digging the texture,
the taste of it.
The dry rub has a really good
kick to it.
You get that crunch.
[ Crunches ]
That was like a tortilla chip
crunch from a commercial
of the late '70s and '80s.
Exactly.
[ Crunch ]
I'm excited you're here,
but this.
This is --
Yeah, I'll leave you alone.
Go, go, go.
Burgers are my thing.
Burgers are your jam?
Too bad you can't eat it.
When I opened this place,
I really came close.
Farmer, cow, and the carrot
is what it should be called.
Yes, exactly.
Come on down.
Excellent, buddy.
Thanks, man.
Up next, in Vancouver...
How much fun is this joint, man?
...a spot that screams
heavy-metal hangout...
Most people, when they walk
in the door,
they think dive bar.
But the food
is a symphony of flavor.
This is not at all
what I expected.
Are you ready now?
Yes.
Wow, the service is fast.
♪♪
I'm here in Vancouver,
Canada, on Hastings,
about 10 minutes from downtown,
and I'm here to check out
a joint
where a girl had a pet store
next to a vacant restaurant.
Well, then she opened up the
restaurant, moved the pet store,
and opened a tattoo shop
where the pet store was.
I know, very confusing,
but you're gonna love it.
Their motto is,
"Beer, food, and metal."
This is Jackalopes
Neighborhood Dive.
♪♪
Hamburger Helpless up.
Jackalopes is food above
what you'd expect
and a crowd maybe
below what you'd expect.
Full order of reaper nachos.
There's a lot of funky stuff
on the walls
and shady looking people,
but you're eating 5-star food.
FIERI: The folks here are
calling it trashy comfort,
with chef Jeff Nicholson
rocking scratch-made plates
and owner Kristy Clark's
heavy metal haven.
How much fun
is this joint, man?
My pet food store
used to be next door.
There was nowhere to hang out
and drink and eat good food,
so when it came available,
I took it 'cause...
Had you been in the
restaurant business before?
Oh, no.
We have very limited space
in our kitchen,
so it was kind of
working around that.
Limited is an understatement.
But out of this tiny
hundred-square-foot space
comes plenty of big flavors.
MAN: If you love meat
or if you're a vegan,
this is definitely
the place for you.
Walnut burger up.
This vegetarian burger is great.
You don't feel like
you're being cheated on,
the fact that
it's not a meat burger?
It just tastes perfect.
I see people wolf them down
all the time.
All right, what are
we making first, Chef?
We're gonna make
the walnut patties.
We got some pretoasted walnuts,
nutritional yeast,
Hungarian paprika, ancho chili,
Morita chili, and cumin.
Gonna buzz this
for a little bit.
And what does
the nutritional yeast do?
It gives it kind of a cheesy,
Earthy kind of flavor.
I got you.
Then we're gonna go in with
the fried onions, maple syrup...
It's, Canada.
And our black beans.
Got it.
We got the rest of the nuts,
ground jasmine rice
that I cook
and then I put flaxseed in it.
It gives it a little bit
of nutty flavor.
A little salt, a little pepper,
some bread crumb.
I make a couple different styles
of veggie patties,
but the walnuts are something
totally new for me.
Bake it for about six minutes,
give it a flip,
put some mixed
mushrooms and cheese on it,
bake it
for another four minutes,
and it's a done deal.
What else goes on this?
My grandma's pickles.
It's the smallest kitchen and
they're gonna make the pickles.
We're using these small
Lebanese cucumbers.
We got some sea salt,
some brown mustard seeds,
granulated onion,
ground celery, and turmeric.
Sugar, apple cider vinegar.
The salt pulls the juice
out of the cucumber
and creates the brine.
How long you let these go?
I like to let them go overnight.
So, that's it?
We got out toasted bun here
that we make in house.
House made?
Yeah, of course.
Mayonnaise that we make
in house,
pickles, lettuce, tomatoes.
That's all she wrote.
That's a hardy burger
right there.
♪♪
That's a better
vegetarian burger
than a lot of meat burgers
I've had.
This concoction with the walnuts
and the rice
and the beans and the flaxseed,
and I love the color that you
pick up from the chilies.
Everything you've done right.
The bun's great, very hardy.
When you roast the burger,
add the mushrooms
and the cheese,
you hit it with the house
made pickles,
your mind says,
"This is a burger."
Nicely done, man.
You do all this work
in this little kitchen?
Yep.
Walnut burger's coming out.
It's really rare to find
a garden burger that's juicy.
The texture is just on
'cause of the nuttiness.
It reminds me of, like,
Thanksgiving dinner in a bun.
FIERI:
But this joint is a far cry
from holidays
at grandma's house.
MAN: I was in here one time
and I heard someone say,
"Hey, could you guys turn
the music down a bit?"
And the bartender said,
"We don't do that around here."
MAN: It is decorated with all
the things you might find
in a 17 year old's bedroom
or in my bedroom,
it really depends.
Most people, when they walk in
the door, they think "dive bar."
But then you have food here
and it's amazing.
Rib dinner.
Every single thing you eat
is just so good.
My favorite is
the wake and bake chicken.
Big piece of juicy chicken
that is just to die for.
MAN: It's got a sausage gravy,
some mashed potatoes,
nice corn flakes on top.
How did this chicken come about?
I needed a new dinner item.
We used to have chicken
and waffles on our menu,
so I just adapted that.
We're gonna start by doing
a dry rub.
We got salt, granulated onion,
Hungarian paprika,
Spanish paprika,
granulated garlic, sugar,
and celery salt.
Chicken breast?
It's gonna get dry rubbed
and then we're gonna add some
milk, egg, sour cream marinade.
Is this gonna get
a flour coating?
It gets a crust.
We got corn flakes, bread crumb,
seasoned flour, sugar,
Spanish paprika,
poultry seasoning,
and ground celery seeds.
Very interesting concoction.
Dredge the chicken,
small amount of canola,
put it in at 500°
for about 10 minutes.
Okay, Chef, next step.
Sausage gravy.
We got ground pork jowls.
Sometimes we breakdown pigs
and grind in house.
Where?
I do not know what's going on
in this kitchen.
We got salt, pepper, fresh sage,
fresh ginger,
maple syrup,
and bread crumbs.
Your own sausage mix
into the hot pan.
Brown it up, and I'm gonna
add some Canadian maple syrup.
What is gonna be the basis of
this gravy besides the sausage?
House rendered pork fat,
some chopped onions and garlic,
fresh thyme, seasoned flour,
chicken stock, and whole milk.
Let that cook for 10 minutes
and it's ready for the sausage.
All right, where we at, buddy?
We got the chicken and we got
the sausage gravy, corn flakes,
and a little bit
of fresh herbs.
Giving it all right there.
It's a real rib sticker.
Bro, this is not at all
what I expected
when I came into
Jackalope.
You and everybody else
that comes in here.
I've had fried chicken
at fried chicken joints
doesn't taste as good
as that chicken.
Great crunch, tons of flavor,
super tender and moist,
baked off, not fried.
Great mashed potatoes,
great carrots,
green beans
cooked perfectly.
It reminds me of that chicken
when you were a kid,
you'd shake it up.
And you really put the
professional chef spin on it.
That's killer.
Two wake and bakes.
MAN: Crispy and just
such juicy chicken.
Try and do something like this
at home and there's just no way.
MAN: The gravy is kind of spicy,
but not too spicy.
Absolutely unbelievable
comfort food.
Beef dip.
If I was gonna tell somebody
to come here, I'd be like,
"Do you want
really great food?
Do you like to have beer
and sit around
and chat
to awesome, rad people?"
Awesome, rad people.
This is the spot to be.
Chef, you had me at dives,
you backed it up with the decor,
funky little kitchen.
When we talk about
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives",
you take the dive award.
Well done.
Coming up, a farm-to-table beer
joint in San Diego...
That's gorgeous.
...firing up a wild take
on meatless...
I would eat one
of those every day.
...and sending sausage
into a whole new territory.
That's the real deal
right there.
♪♪
So, I'm here in San Diego,
California,
about five minutes
from downtown.
This is an area
known as North Park.
And you know what?
If I'm not mistaken,
I think about a mile
that way is Luigi's Pizzeria.
Anyhow, if you're from here,
you know this is
the area you come to
to find the local breweries,
and I can't wait to find out
what's behind this name.
This is Tiger! Tiger!
♪♪
Kielbasa in the window.
Tiger! Tiger!
is a cool hangout.
They're known for their
farm-to-table food.
Pork belly bánh mí up.
It's a great environment,
great people,
great food, great beer.
What more can you ask for?
Another great.
How 'bout the two great couples
who opened this spot?
Jeff Motch and Clea Hantman
and Jennifer and Lee Chase.
What is the menu?
It moves around with local farms
bringing us things they have.
We let the chefs take over
and we just told them
we wanted it
to go good with beer.
Tinga, to the window.
FIERI: And chef Sharon Wilson's
taking that challenge
and running with it.
Hot-mushroom sandwich here.
The beach mushroom is awesome
because it's --
It's beachin'.
I mean, it really --
Sorry, I had to try it.
It has a really
good spice to it.
Amazing.
-What are we making?
The hot-mushroom sandwich.
We're making the brine
for the pickled celery.
It's gonna be part of the slaw.
White vinegar, sugar, celery
seed, coriander seed,
turmeric, mustard seed, salt.
And then pour this hot brine
over the celery and the onions.
How long are we gonna
let that steep?
Overnight.
This gets combined with what?
Thinly sliced cabbage.
Dig it!
What's this setup?
This is a slurry of corn starch
and water.
Man, I've seen
a lot of slurries.
We always usually make them
about that much if we're
ever gonna make one.
Mm-hmm.
I've never seen that
gelatinous mass.
That's why we did this whole...
Look at this.
Is is always the same mushroom?
Yeah, we use the beach.
Oh, don't break it.
I didn't.
Put it back!
[ Whistling ]
I'll be over here.
It gets a little bath in there.
This is the glue that's gonna
hold on the flour.
One big monster.
Oh, looks like somebody
broke it!
Somebody broke it.
And we're gonna fry this thing?
Yeah.
All right, Chef.
We can make our spice mix.
Hit it.
Cayenne, smoked paprika,
onion powder,
black pepper, brown sugar,
and salt.
Okay.
Grab our mushroom, drizzle
a little bit of oil in there.
This is what's gonna make
that seasoning stick on there.
Like Nashville hot chicken.
Yeah.
Next up?
Bread.
Scallion aioli, mushrooms,
and then we'll add our slaw.
This is like the Calgon of
Flavortown -- take me away.
I'm gonna release the jaw.
Is there any right here?
Just a little.
I would eat one of those
every day.
You've got my favorite things
going on here --
you've got the acid,
you've got the salt,
and you've got the heat.
And then you fry anything --
you can fry a flip flop.
That bite right there with some
of that scallion aioli
and the pickled celery
and onions with the cabbage.
If you just told somebody it was
a Nashville hot sandwich,
I think people would flip out
when they
found out it's a mushroom.
That's outstanding.
I'm trying really hard not
to eat the whole thing.
We have a hot-mushroom
sandwich for you.
It's perfectly fried.
It's, like,
crispy all the way through.
That sandwich has a lot of nooks
and crannies
in that beach mushroom
where it captures all of
that flavor of the breading
and it's a little bit
spicy and...
You're trying to take my job,
aren't you?
You're fired.
Don't put her on the show.
Burger, mid rare.
Not a lot of places have
the local beers and the food.
It's got, like, a real cool,
like, family vibe to it.
Why are we calling it
"Tiger! Tiger!"?
Are you a "Brady Bunch" fan?
Of course.
Remember when
they lost Tiger?
Right.
And they do the close-up
of the dog house
and there's the two bowls
next to each other
and they say Tiger! Tiger!
And Bobby runs out on the street
yelling, "Tiger! Tiger!"
How much did you have to drink
before you came up
with that name?
Anytime that I come here,
it's just a really fun
place to be.
So, when we come back,
what are we gonna make?
Chicken-shawarma sausage.
I love the chicken shawarma.
It's all the flavors that you
would get off of a rotisserie
put into a sausage.
We'll see you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in San Diego
at Tiger! Tiger!
Tiger! Tiger! --
they're one of the first places
to really start the craft beer
farm-to-table here in San Diego.
FIERI: And Chef Sharon's tying
the pub to the grub
with new takes
on old standards.
Two shawarmas!
This right here is the
chicken-shawarma sausage.
It's juicy.
The tzatziki sauce counters
the red pepper sauce,
so it's hot and then it's cool
and refreshing at the same time.
Chicken shawarma sausage.
Chicken shawarma sausage, yeah.
Say that 10 times in a row.
Chicken shawarma swa--
I can't even say it once.
We got out chicken thighs
and chicken skins.
We marinade them
two different ways.
This is gonna be
the grilled chicken.
Olive oil, lemon juice, yogurt,
a little salt and pepper.
It gets marinated overnight
and then it's gonna get grilled.
The raw chicken gets marinated
with onions and garlic and salt.
This is also 24 hours?
24 hours and then they're gonna
have two different grinds.
After that's grilled,
that's a bigger grind
so you get
those chunks in there.
And this gets ground
a little finer.
The body and the highlights.
Exactly.
Now we're gonna put
all these seasonings together
and this is gonna be
the base to come together
for chicken
shawarma sausage?
I said it.
First, we add the raw chicken,
coriander and cumin,
milk powder, smoked paprika,
cinnamon, garlic powder,
the sausage phosphate.
Dr. Sausage Phosphate,
Dr. Sausage Phosphate.
Allspice, parsley, cayenne,
black pepper,
onion powder, oregano...
Cardamom?
And lemon zest.
Now in with the grilled
ground thighs.
Yeah.
Got it.
Now we're gonna case
our chicken shawarma.
In the oven.
Mm-hmm.
After they're cooked, we'll
finish them on the char grill.
Okay, anything else
on top of it?
The kabob-chopped hot sauce.
Kabob chop -- and we're
gonna make it?
Kabob chop, yeah.
Kabob chop.
Onion, jalapeño, garlic,
some salt, sambal...
A little vinegar.
And I'm gonna zap
that a quick second
and then I'll add my tomato.
Okay.
So, we are gonna plate up
our toasty brioche bun.
Sausage going in.
The tzatziki.
This is our kabob hot sauce.
Homemade potato salad,
a little bit of pickle,
little bit of onion.
That's gorgeous.
I mean, that's like
real chicken shawarma.
The yogurt coming through,
the char of the chicken thigh,
the fattiness you're getting
from the skin,
there's a lot of moisture in it,
it's not overly salty,
it's not too heavy in the spice,
the tzatziki comes through.
That's the real deal
right there.
Awesome.
Chicken shawarma sausage.
The chicken shawarma,
it's really juicy
and then the tzatziki on top
is so perfect.
Chili sauce, it accompanies
the sweetness of the sausage.
Truffle parm fry up.
There's not a lot of places
that do really good food
and really good beer.
What's better,
the beer or the food?
The way the pair together.
Whoo, good answer!
Mrs. and Mrs. Smart over here.
Burger and a chicken shawarma.
A lot of people who come
into town stop by here
because they hear
a lot of real good things
about it and rightfully so.
It's something special.
If you're gonna have a funky
name like Tiger! Tiger!,
the food better
speak in volumes,
and it really does.
Awesome.
Legit.
So, that's it for this
road trip, but don't worry!
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
My first horse
I had was named Jasper.
And I have another nickname,
but I'm not telling you
what that is.
Oh, I want to know.
My nickname's Vicki.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
Who here knows that Jasper's
other name is Vicki?
Who now knows that Jasper's
SINGH: I knew I shouldn't have
told you that.