You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
"Triple D," how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
You were expecting
a Flavortown reference.
I know you were.
...it's a fiesta
in Salt Lake City...
I can't wait
for this.
...with mouthwatering Mexican,
no matter how you eat it.
Serve it in my hand
or in my shoe or my pocket.
And...
Trying not to
jiggle too much.
[ Laughing ]
Try not to jiggle.
...an old-school
breakfast spot...
Does your mom know
that you took this from her?
...feeding the A.M. crowd
all day in Arizona.
Look at that thing.
A diner in Boulder City, Nevada,
churning out killer chili.
Oh, my God.
And in San Diego...
Call your mommy,
that's a lot of pastrami.
...I'm checking in
on a "Triple D" OG...
Go ahead and show them
the weirdness.
...making sure the "Bossman's"
legacy is living on.
You're the best.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, if you've watched "Triple D"
in the last 12 years,
you got to know about
this "Triple D" OG
here in Ocean Beach,
California.
Now, unfortunately,
four years ago,
we lost the "Bossman."
But his son Shane,
he's got the reins,
and he's doing a great job.
It's time to check in.
This is Hodad's.
A Blue Jay and a Frank
for surfboard three.
If you want a real, good burger,
this is the place to be.
Saw Hodad's on "Triple D,"
and I had to come down
and try it out.
FIERI: The question is,
which time?
'Cause I've hit this place
up twice, first in '07...
Trough it.
Look at that.
...and again in 2013.
It just gets more and more
out-of-bounds.
Go ahead and show them
the weirdness.
Yahoo!
Look at that, huh?
Because you can never
get enough
of the late,
great "Bossman" Mike Hardin.
I guess I'll take over.
So, anyway, what we do is,
we sell burgers.
Is this thing on?
Hold on.
I'm busy.
And since I'm in San Diego
for "Triple D" again,
you know I got to stop in.
But this time it's a little
bittersweet
'cause we lost
the "Bossman" back in 2015,
but he can be proud
of his son Shane,
who's taken over the family biz.
How long ago was it that we shot
"Triple D" here the first time?
11 years ago.
So, 11 years.
I was 16.
You were 16?
You were a kid.
Yeah.
So, who's
the milkshake master?
This guy right here.
It's the guy
with two thumbs.
This guy.
When we came here
the first time,
I didn't have any idea
who your dad was.
I didn't know what
an institution "Hodad's" was.
HARDIN: Yeah.
What is this?
It's bacon.
I don't like two little
strips of bacon,
so we came up with this.
Like the rest of the world
makes bacon cheeseburgers.
Exactly.
You don't want to
follow that.
We want to make, like,
a bacon patty.
That's what this does.
So, you boil
the bacon in water.
On the grill, looks
almost like hash browns.
What's it wrapped in?
The burger diaper,
and once you pick it up,
don't let it go,
you know?
You got to coddle
the baby.
We give lessons
on Wednesdays.
This one's not
doing it right.
Have you not been
to the Wednesday lesson?
When you get done, we'll
hose you off out back, alright?
Mmm.
The bacon patty thing,
that's out-of-bounds, man.
And the entire
Fieri family agree.
It's the best burger
I've ever ate.
Really?
Yep.
"Probably the best burger
I've ever ate"?
That's a lot
coming from Hunter.
FIERI:
Give me the update.
Where's the world
of "Hodad's"?
The most recent burger
on the menu is, I think,
when your dad and I
put the Guido on the menu.
Guido, yep.
Still does good?
Oh, yeah.
It's killing it.
You've been asking me
for a couple years
to make
a pastrami burger.
So, you made it?
Yeah.
Everyone who knows Guy knows
his nickname's Guido,
so we thought it would be
a great idea to come up
with something to put on
the menu to say thanks to him.
"Oh, no. He's not gonna put
this much pastrami on.
Oh, no, wait.
How much is he putting on?"
Call your mommy,
that's a lot of pastrami.
Isn't that something?
[ Laughs ]
Crème de la crème,
whatever that means.
We use
a brown mustard.
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my gosh.
Look at that.
And that's the Guido?
That's it.
Oh, there we go.
Look at that.
I like how you crisp it up
on the flattop
and the Swiss cheese.
The burger is righteous.
When somebody names a burger
of this magnitude after you,
I love you, man.
You're the bomb.
[ Laughs ]
Thanks, brother.
Cheers.
What else?
We opened up
our spot downtown.
You were already busy
as it was.
Yes.
"Hodad's" was already
slammed.
Yes.
So you made a second
location downtown.
We needed a new venue.
When we opened downtown,
we debuted the Blue Jay.
The Blue Jay has been
selling like crazy.
We're stoked.
HARDIN: It has
our house blue cheese,
buttermilk, mayonnaise,
blue cheese crumbles.
We're gonna stir it
all together.
We're gonna throw
some onions on the grill.
Throw down some butter
and seasoned salt.
Then we're gonna use
some of our beer.
We started brewing our own beer,
the Throwback Brown.
Kind of gives it a little bit
of a nuttiness,
almost like a chocolate feel.
1/3 of a pound patty.
Season it up.
We're gonna put
some hash marks in.
This is a trick that my dad
taught me,
to cook even
all the way through.
Throw the bacon
on top of the beef patty.
We're gonna start with some
mayo there, some mustard,
pickles, a slice of tomato
and what we call
"the lettuce snowball."
Top it with our beef patty,
our bacon patty,
the grilled onions,
the blue cheese and the top bun.
We'll wrap it
in our burger diaper.
I've got two Blue Jays.
Let's go.
MAN: The blue cheese,
it's incredible.
They've got one of those
bacon patties.
It's something I've never
had before, and it's awesome.
Is the van
still here?
The van is...
It is physically here.
The first thing
I say is...
And I didn't even know
it was yours, and I just said,
"Look at that little
mini wagon out there."
Isn't that great?
And I'm going, "Look at
the wheelbase on that thing.
I wouldn't take it
over 30."
I really think we should
rebuild this.
It's gonna be a project.
Ah.
If we took a quarter
from every burger...
Yes.
...we could have this
done in, what?
We need your money.
MAN:
Call [Echoing] now.
Tell them. Give them
your campaign speech.
Please help.
We need money.
Donate now,
for just pennies a day.
For just pennies
a day.
[ Laughs ]
For just the price
of Guy's car.
of that car.
Call now.
Call [Echoing] now.
♪♪
Did you ever think
Food Network would be coming?
There ain't no way.
Mmm.
Awesome.
[ Laughs ]
You're the best.
♪♪
Now, that is one brother
I miss a lot,
but Shane is doing a bang-up job
keeping his dad's legacy alive,
and I'm sure that the "Bossman"
couldn't be prouder.
Now, coming up...
It looks like a hiking boot
just walked on a pancake.
...a breakfast all-day diner
blowing up all over Arizona.
Matt's Big Breakfast Counseling
and Development Center
for those that do not appreciate
the early morning cuisine.
It's catchy.
Yeah.
♪♪
Back in 2007 in downtown
Phoenix,
I checked out
this tiny breakfast joint
that was drawing quite a crowd.
These days, they've got
three new locations,
and the original moved
into a way bigger joint,
but there's still a line
out the door.
This is Matt's Big Breakfast.
Home-cooked,
awesome food.
It's just so fun to bring the
kids and get yummy breakfast.
They haven't lost
their consistency.
The food always comes out
nice and hot.
You know what you're going to
get when you walk into Matt's.
How are you doing?
How's your breakfast?
FIERI: That's because
owner Matt Pool
keeps this old-school
mom-and-pop diner old school.
Does your mom know
you took this from here?
I mean, because in '72 they quit
making the parts for this one.
You make the batter for pancakes
and make the batter for...
For the waffles.
Same exact batter.
You want to help me crack,
or should I just do it all?
Well, I've never cracked
in tandem before.
[ Chuckles ]
We got 2 cups
of sugar here.
We're gonna put some butter
in there.
Put it in melted.
Now, you're not worried
about kind of poaching
those eggs a little bit
with that hot butter?
We'd worry if I didn't
start whisking.
Okay.
Trying not to jiggle
too much.
[ Laughing ]
Try not to jiggle.
Sucking it in.
[ Laughs ]
The flour
and the whole milk,
we're gonna add them
in alternate doses here.
Then we add
the baking powder.
It's just
a teaspoon of salt.
Looks like cake batter.
So, you flip it
back over.
It looks like a hiking boot
just walked on a pancake.
Look at that thing.
That's a hot Frisbee
of fun.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm.
It's got a really
nice crust to it.
Look at it,
inside there.
You see how nice
and light and airy.
POOL: Guy doesn't
eat eggs,
and as the owner
of Matt's Big Breakfast,
I thought,
"Well, this is a problem."
But we were able to
kind of work around that.
FIERI:
The waffles were a start,
but Matt's also got
other options
for non-egg lovers,
like his biscuits and gravy.
POOL:
We do it every Tuesday.
We really get a real boost
in business.
We make the gravy
from scratch.
The key ingredient for us
is the sausage.
It's got a real red chili
kick to it.
We're gonna add a little bit
of flour,
some whole milk, fresh cracked
black pepper, and sea salt.
Once that all comes together,
it's ready to go
on top of our
homemade biscuits.
Biscuit and gravy.
I love their gravy 'cause
the sausage that they use
has just
the right amount of spice.
The sausage and the gravy
kind of have this peppery,
almost spicy taste to them
but just enough.
The biscuits are so fluffy.
All together, it's just amazing.
Tell me about the pork
chop phenomenon.
POOL: Well, we've got
a rib chop here,
and then we make
a pesto marinade.
Commercial grade.
Commercial,
fancy restaurant.
We've got
the smart power here.
We put the garlic
in there first,
about 1 1/2 ounces
of fresh basil,
pine nuts, sea salt, pepper,
and then extra virgin olive oil,
and you just kind of
do this by sight.
Look at the color
in that.
I've got some chops here.
Gonna get a nice,
little crust on it.
POOL: Looks like
it's time to flip.
Those bad boys
got to be done.
You want to give them
a shot?
You're nervous.
Is he really gonna
like our food?
Oh. Fantastic.
I mean, it seemed like
he really liked it.
[ Both laugh ]
FIERI: But that pesto isn't
the only scratch sauce he's got.
It's a verde sauce
that's made with tomatillos.
We serve it on huevos rancheros.
We add a little bit
of extra virgin olive oil.
Then we put them in the oven
for about 45 minutes.
We blend them to a fine pulp.
Then they're ready
for the salsa verde.
And then we're gonna
just heat some onions
and garlic, fresh jalapeños,
and some Roma tomatoes.
Once that's sauteed,
we're gonna add
our pureed roasted tomatillos,
our butter,
and that just adds
a little bit more savory note.
We're gonna finish it off
with fresh cilantro,
sea salt,
and cracked black pepper.
We serve it with organic
pinto beans, two corn tortillas,
two eggs cooked to order,
salsa verde,
a little bit of Cotija cheese,
and fresh cilantro.
Huevo ranchero.
It's got a really nice flavor
from the tomato.
It just makes the whole dish.
The tomatillo sauce
is a bright,
spicy, sweet sauce
that you can put over your eggs.
It's like hot sauce
but in the southwest.
Now, what will the wait
turn into, like,
on an average weekday
or weekend?
Hour and a half.
To get in?
Oh, yeah.
And it's worth the wait,
for sure.
Since then, we've opened
in our airport here,
and then central Phoenix
and then
a much bigger place in Tempe.
FIERI: They've also moved
the original joint
to a bigger place
on the same block.
What do you like
about it here?
My daddy owns it.
We still think of ourselves
as a mom-and-pop shop.
My wife is still here every day,
and our son,
he now works in the kitchen.
Bacon coming in.
I love that part.
Matt's Big Breakfast Counseling
and Development Center
for those that do not appreciate
the early morning cuisine.
It's catchy.
Yeah.
♪♪
Blowing up the four locations,
next time we check in,
who knows how many he'll have.
And speaking of going big,
we're headed
to Salt Lake City...
That's half
the size of you.
...where you can find burritos
that are busting at the seams.
You got to get
the football hold.
[ Laughs ]
Now when I'm driving around
the '68 Camaro,
there aren't too many other cars
that give me car envy.
And a Mexican place
in the middle of Salt Lake City
was the last place
I was expecting
to find any competition
for my Camaro.
But when I find a joint
that's got a car this sick,
well, I just got to stop
and check it out.
And it was worth it.
This is Lone Star Taqueria.
♪♪
WOMAN: The Lone Star Taqueria
has the most delicious food.
It's really fresh,
and it's always been excellent.
Having "Triple D" here
was a great deal,
definitely put on the map.
Standing on top of the car
wasn't a bad idea either.
FIERI:
The proud owner of that car
and the joint it's in front of,
is Susan Harries.
Even swap the Camaro
for the station wagon?
Even swap?
Oh, absolutely not.
Okay. I'll give you
500 bucks.
[ Laughs ]
No way.
I wouldn't even take
$5,000 for it.
[ Laughs ]
So I struck out on the car,
but the food, that's a home run.
So, what are we gonna
make now?
Shrimp burritos.
Bell peppers.
Okay.
Garlic, cayenne,
black pepper.
We gonna put it
all in?
Depends on...
California chili.
A little salt,
New Mexico chili.
And then a little bit
of the...
Soybean oil.
Soybean oil?
Soybean.
Wow.
How gauche of you.
So saute that up.
Add the shrimp.
And we go fast with these,
right?
Yep.
Now we have our peppers.
Look how juicy
already.
We got our rice.
We got some of our beans.
Just a little bit
of cheese.
Now the camarones.
Don't forget
that guy.
Oh, that guy
right there.
Mmm.
Oh, that's killer.
What's that called,
killer burrito?
This place has definitely got
their surf game on,
and for the turf?
Oh, they're
crushing that, too.
HARRIES: The boys used to make
this concoction
back in the prep area.
It just looked so delicious, and
we'd just make it just for us.
I said, "Well, that's going
on our menu."
Taco Especial are
"what the boys eat."
It starts with the carne
adovada.
Everybody in the pool?
Yeah.
Everybody in the pool.
Now we're gonna
marinate it. Cumin.
Okay, cayenne.
Cayenne.
The garlic.
California chili.
New Mexico, clove,
bay leaf, salt.
Uh-huh.
Aceite, the oil.
You were expecting
a Flavortown reference.
I know you were.
Sit, like,
maybe overnight.
I can't wait for this.
Oh-ho-ho-ho-ho.
We got a piece.
See how tender it is?
Go ahead and try a piece.
Doggone.
Serve it in my hand
or in my shoe or my pocket.
That is really good.
FIERI: But when it's going
into the Especial,
it's served with even more meat.
We added our carne asada,
which is steak, top round,
marinated in cloves, bay leaves,
garlic, salt, and pepper.
Soybean oil,
and then we grill it.
Next we start with mixing
the carne asada,
the carne adovada
and the fresh vegetables
that we chop all together.
We throw that back on
the flat top with some onions.
Saute that for a few minutes,
and then we put it into
a 16-inch flour tortilla
with rice, beans, cilantro,
onions, cheese, sour cream.
Roll it up and hand it out.
Absolutely delicious.
It has all the meats
you could want, the veggies.
And plus, when it's almost
the size of my head,
[Laughs] I eat it,
and I'm full as can be.
The flavors are so interesting,
and it's "what the boys eat."
The girls probably eat
more than the boys eat.
[ Chuckles ]
Did you really
order that?
That's half
the size of you.
You got to get
the football hold.
How many meals
do we do a day?
Between 400 to 500.
Now we're doing over
1,000 meals a day.
"Triple D" helped us grow.
And you're kind of, like,
the mayor of this...
I watch everybody come in.
You know everybody.
Yes.
I'm impressed.
You had me at "hello."
I'll be back, okay?
I will be back.
And if you're back
in Salt Lake City,
keep an eye out for that car.
Grab a burrito the size
of your head,
and tell them Guy sent you.
Now coming up in Nevada,
a family-run restaurant...
You are a character.
...doing diner food
the right way.
No, that chili
is the Schnitz-nad.
AL: [ Laughs ]
FIERI: Now, back in 2007,
one of the very first "Triple D"
joints I went to
was in Boulder City, Nevada,
right near my old college
stomping grounds.
It's been here for 75 years,
helped feed all the guys
while they were building
the Hoover Dam.
And thanks to keeping it all
in the family,
it's still going strong.
This is the Coffee Cup Cafe.
Kahuna burger,
chili dog burrito, order up.
[ Bell dings ]
Comfort food at its finest.
We are hard-core
Coffee Cup patrons.
The food is delicious.
The owners are wonderful.
FIERI: He's talking about
the Stevens family.
And back in 2007,
it was Carri and Al
running the joint with the help
from their daughter Lindsay.
I'm the orchestra leader.
I go over there, over here,
over here, and he is that way.
How long have you
worked here, Linds?
Since I was little.
You gonna be
taking this over?
Is this Lindsay's future?
It's always been
a thought.
And look what happened.
My parents are pretty
much retired,
so me and my brother have been
taking over the past few years.
FIERI: And while Carri and Al
might not be there every day,
their recipes sure are.
I am a pork chili verde
machine.
Whose recipe is this?
This is mine.
This is pork butt
and pork cushion.
It's been simmering
for how long?
Probably about
3 to 4 hours.
Okay. Now we're gonna
drain off this pork juice.
Now we're gonna put in
some actual green chiles.
Cilantro goes in
and jalapeño.
This is where the guesswork
comes in
'cause it could be
on fire or...
Well, you never know
with the jalapeños...
You never know.
...how it's gonna go.
Those big chunks, and you can
see that jalapeño in there.
This is the verde
back here?
AL: That's the verde,
ready to rock.
Mmm.
That's great
on huevos, man.
Mmm. Wow.
We just had it as a special
back then.
Then it got put on the menu.
It's definitely
a number-one seller.
This is how I keep
my girlish figure...
Yes.
...is that I only take little
bites, princess bites.
We make our chili from scratch,
too, every day.
You make the chili, too?
Yep.
Brown the ground beef,
and we add the diced onions,
beef bouillon, chili powder,
ground black pepper in it,
seasoned salt, cumin,
red pepper flakes,
granulated garlic.
And we add the diced tomatoes,
spiced chili beans,
tomato sauce.
Simmer for about 30 minutes.
That chili is
the Schnitz-nad.
Okay. Let me tell you
another thing you could make.
Tortilla and some of the chili
over the top with some lettuce
and some cheese and some avocado
and some sour cream.
He's like, "This would be great
on a tortilla,"
so we actually do
the chili dog burrito.
Sour cream, French fries,
cheddar cheese, house red chili,
grilled diced onions, jalapeños,
all-beef hot dog, bacon.
Chili dog burrito.
A little spicy.
You can taste the chili.
It really complements
the hot dog in there
as well as the jalapeño.
Who would think to put
a chili dog with bacon
and French fries in a burrito?
But, man, that was so good.
Are you keeping an eye
on things over here, Jay?
Oh, yeah.
It's burning.
[ Laughs ]
One of our cooks, Jay,
was in the episode back in 2007.
And you've been here
for a year and a half?
A year and a half.
Nice.
And he's still here now.
He has such great ideas.
We've added Jay's chicken
sandwich, the Godfather Omelet.
We added the Kahuna Burger.
It's really popular.
We grill a one-third-pound
burger patty, smoked ham,
two slices of the pineapple,
shredded cheddar cheese,
Thousand Island,
teriyaki sauce, lettuce, onion.
Everything is all stacked on,
piled high.
Kahuna Burger, order up.
It's sweet and sour.
The combination's delicious.
It's an explosion of flavors.
It's got a great sauce on it.
Tried to eat it with both hands,
and it was trying
to get away from me,
so I'm using a knife
and fork to make sure
I get every little bit.
Is it what you thought
it was gonna be?
I think it's better
than what I thought it would be.
It's fun.
I enjoy the people,
a lot of characters.
Good to see
you guys again.
You are a character.
It's a wonderful life.
All is good.
I mean, why even do it
if you don't love it, right?
These guys put so much
of themselves into their joints.
I'm just glad that the nation
has taken notice.
[ Both laugh ]
Like Hodad's in San Diego, where
things are still smooth sailing,
even though we lost
the "Bossman."
And at Matt's,
whose big breakfast has expanded
all over Arizona.
In Salt Lake City,
where the Lone Star Taqueria
is still serving up
real-deal Mexican to the masses.
And the Coffee Cup Cafe
in Boulder City
that's still
putting family first.
But those, ladies and gentlemen,
aren't the only ones.
We'll check in on more diners,
drive-ins, and dives
next time on
"Triple D Nation."
[ Thud ]
Oh.
That's gonna leave
a mark.
MAN: Are you all right?
Drilled it.
I even bent it.
That so hurt.
MAN:
Are you okay?
You all right, bro?