Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
I'm gonna drown in my own drool,
you know that?
FIERI:
...it's a deep dive...
Live on the edge.
Come on!
FIERI: ...into some
off-the-hook seafood.
You can't get it
any fresher than that.
FIERI:
We've got fried in Vancouver...
Shut the front
and back door.
FIERI:
...Thai in California...
It's not great.
It's phenomenal.
FIERI: ...and no joke-ay poke
in Hawaii...
Creamy, spicy,
nutty, crunchy.
FIERI:
...packed with a flavor bomb.
That's hot.
-Hoo!
Oh, my gosh.
You're sweating.
[ Laughter ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives."
♪♪
Nothing better than cruising
around the island of Kauai
with my right-hand man
Hunter.
Hunter,
what are we hungry for?
-Poke.
-Exactly.
Now, Dad, how do you find
the best poke?
You know,
what do you look for?
Well, I mean,
there's places all over,
but I got to tell you --
you talk to the locals,
you look around, and when
you pull into a parking lot
and you see a line like that,
you got to check it out.
This is Hanalei Poke.
We got a spicy Village.
It's just such a -- mmm! --
wonderful taste experience.
I'll drive halfway across
the island to have it.
We got a Local Boy.
So, there's awesome
poke places everywhere.
Yeah.
What do you think
sets it apart?
The fresh ingredients.
FIERI:
Like really fresh,
'cause Jeremy Burwell's
personal fish guy is...
Jeremy Burwell.
I started selling fish
to, like, little restaurants.
And then decided to keep
his catch for his own spot.
Why does everybody flock
to the little truck?
The quality of our fish.
We go the extra mile
the way we cut it --
very small pieces.
That way,
no one ever gets that,
like, big old, chewy
sinew ahi piece.
This, to me,
is probably one of
the most important things
you can learn.
Can you teach Hunter?
Sure.
These are Koshibi.
It's a small ahi.
Start at the head.
-That's a fin.
-Tail, fin, whatever.
-Yeah, you go...
-Wing.
This meat comes
all the way to here.
[ Laughing ]
Did you call it a wing?
HUNTER: Oh, you make it
look so easy.
That all right?
God, I'm all nervous,
like he's playing
Little League
or something,
like, "Swing the bat!"
It's like "Operation."
Now we're gonna
turn it around for you.
Now you're, like, lifting,
just like that.
Right in the ice.
[ Whispering ] Put that
in the back of the car.
[ Normal voice ]
Cube all this,
and now we start
to build the bowl.
Yeah.
FIERI: And he's mixing things up
with what he's mixing in.
BURWELL:
Kealia Plate with sushi rice.
Kealia Bowl's great because
it's got some fruit in there,
and nuts as well.
He brings in a new flair that
just makes it really amazing.
Okay, let's see it.
BURWELL: This is how we make
our sushi rice.
First, we wet our hangiri so
the rice doesn't stick to it.
Nice, big hangiri
you got here.
When you're making
sushi rice,
this makes all the difference
in the world
to get that rice right,
absorbing the moisture.
Yep.
Okay, so the rice is cooked
inside this rice bag.
-Sugar.
-Rice wine vinegar.
Pour it over the rice.
I'm just folding it
in there.
-Excellent.
-All right.
We're gonna do the Kealia.
Fresh ahi, fresh ono,
green onion,
fresh limu right here.
Seaweed.
And we'll throw
a little bit of red onion,
mango, watermelon,
beautiful local avocados.
You got
fresh everything, man.
Fresh mint, basil,
cilantro grown on-site
right over here
in the garden,
macadamia nuts,
just a little bit of inamona.
Inamona.
What is inamona?
It's roasted kukui nut.
And some red pepper.
And this is our
sesame-oil Sriracha mix.
And that looks good.
Finishing touch --
our chili-pepper shoyu.
Kealia Plate.
Where's your plate?
Taking my lines?
Mmm.
I'm trying
all kinds of flavors
I've never had
in a poke bowl --
the mint,
the watermelon.
That watermelon is
so good in there.
That is so refreshing.
Really nice.
The kukui with the mint --
game changer.
You've got creamy, spicy,
salty, nutty, crunchy.
The macadamia nut --
it makes the salad even better.
-It really does.
-It does.
That's ono-licious
right there.
-Yeah.
-That is delicious.
We got a Kealia Plate.
I love the spice.
It's kind of just got
a little bit of everything.
Shoyu sauce on top of the rice
goes really well.
It's a little bit of salty.
WOMAN:
I love the fruit in it.
Ah! With the watermelon
and the mint?
Yeah,
nowhere else does that.
Everything is sourced
on-island, mostly.
He's got a little garden
in walking distance.
WOMAN #2: He's taken
a Hawaiian local staple
and made it a whole different
thing, a whole new twist.
We have a Hanalei Special
over sushi rice.
Awesome.
WOMAN #3:
I love Jeremy's Hanalei Bowl.
It's got tender
little pieces of poke,
all the fruit.
It's got the nuts.
It is amazing.
It's like a medley for my mouth.
-What are we gonna do now?
-Hanalei Special.
And we're gonna start off
with half ahi, half ono.
This is what
I want a bottle of.
The chili shoyu --
how do you make it?
Sugar, soy sauce,
Hawaiian chili peppers.
-Is that these?
-Yep.
[ Whistles ]
Grown on-site in
the garden right over here.
Hunter, do you want to
try one of these?
I -- no. I'll give you
100 bucks of your own money
to eat one of those.
I'll take a little bite.
-That's the bite?
-That's a nibble.
That's super hot.
The look!
Bro, you don't have
a poker face on that one.
-It's hot.
-That's hot. Hunter?
Why would you
do this to me?
The yellow one, yeah.
Come on.
That'll get you going.
Oh, my gosh.
You're sweating.
The whole film crew
had to try a bite.
How hot is that, Neal?
100.
[ Laughter ]
The whole team is dying.
The whole bowl!
-That was a terrible idea.
-Chef, where are we?
Little green onion
and then sweet onion,
red onion, limu, mango,
local avocado,
roasted kukui nut,
Furikake,
roast seaweed,
sesame seeds,
sea salt, sugar,
and then we're gonna spice
it up with some chili oil.
Wow! That's good.
Chili-pepper shoyu.
-So delicate with it.
-You got to be.
Look at that.
Delicious.
Wow. Mmm!
Oh, my God.
This has got a little sweet,
got a little heat,
some crunch.
Mango, avocado, of course,
play well together.
The chili-pepper oil
is next level.
That gets you.
-I think I lost my taste buds.
Good. Then I'll have
the rest of it.
I'll tell you how it tastes.
I'll get back to you.
Hold on. Let me try it again.
Maybe it's a fluke.
There's no fluke in this.
Delicious.
We got a Hanalei Special
over sushi rice.
MAN: Hanalei Special's probably
the most traditional.
The chili-pepper shoyu sauce
gives the poke the kick.
You've got the Furikake in there
to have that little
seaweed flavor.
More flavor than regular
places on the island.
We got a spicy ahi sushi roll.
Do yourself a favor
and go to Hanalei Poke.
This is the best spot
on the island, for sure.
-Well done, my brother.
-That was awesome.
Where you going
with that?
I thought you were
getting your own bowl.
We were having that
together.
I'll get this.
Pay the tab.
-Okay.
-Good talk.
FIERI: Up next --
a so-much-more-than-sushi spot
in Chico, California...
Look at this guy.
You got too much time
on your hands.
FIERI: ...steaming up
seafood treasures...
That's fantastic.
FIERI: ...and throwing a modern
twist into a traditional dish.
Is it real deal?
Trust me -- real deal.
♪♪
So I'm here
in Chico, California.
Now, if you haven't been
to Chico, you're missing it.
The people are awesome,
and the food's dynamite.
And we're here to
check out a restaurant
that has been crushing the
Asian fusion for about 18 years.
This is The Rawbar.
Sacramento, and your
lemon hamachi for you.
Some people think of Rawbar,
they just think of sushi.
But there's a whole lot more
than just sushi.
Table 3 -- beef noodle.
You can get things from
all over the Asian world.
FIERI: And those Asian flavors
were hard to come by in Chico
when restaurant vet
Darren Chadderdon
moved here from San Fran
20 years ago.
The elephant
in the room is...
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I'm trying to hit the gym
a little bit.
The other one.
Why's this Irish-Scottish guy
own a fusion Asian sushi bar?
-Yes.
-'Cause we missed it.
We kind of took it upon
ourselves to do it ourselves.
FIERI: With the help of
a little Asian immersion.
I went to Thailand and started
taking cooking classes up there.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I teach Thai classes now
because of my passion for it.
Table 10 rush -- Tom Kha Gai.
This Tom Kha Gai steamer --
it's definitely got
some Thai flavor in it
with some coconut milk.
Clam steamers, mussels,
scallops, shrimp.
If you're into seafood,
it's awesome.
So what are
we gonna get into?
A Tom Kha Gai steamer.
We're gonna start off
with a Nam Prik Pao,
which is a kind of
a sweet Thai chili paste.
Toasted Thai chilies,
dried shrimp, kosher salt.
And I do warn you, this might
choke you up a little bit
fume-wise.
I hate when it happens.
Culinary technique.
Such a good thing
for the base of the blender.
This is oil that I roasted
the garlic and the shallots in.
Add my dry ingredients.
So while that's toasting,
I'll add the palm sugar --
a little bit
more umami in it
than regular
granular sugar.
Roasted shallots,
a little roasted garlic,
galangal root --
a unique flavor there --
tamarind -- this is
our sour component --
shrimp paste.
You do too much
of that shrimp paste,
it's gonna blow
the whole dish up.
Yeah. Fresh coriander,
just a little bit of water.
I'm gonna drown in my own drool,
you know that?
Slurry that all together.
Before I blend it,
we add the fish sauce
and the lime juice
to finish it off.
So this is not
curry in a hurry.
Definitely.
-That's fantastic.
-Thank you.
All right, next up.
We're gonna make our broth
for our steamer dish.
It is kind of an infusion,
or like making tea.
Hit it.
Coconut milk, water,
fresh chopped
bruised lemongrass,
fresh galangal root,
and then lastly
some Thai chilies.
I don't want to get
too crazy hot,
but this gives it
a nice fruity bite.
Drop that right in.
Sugar salt, fresh lime juice,
fish sauce,
and then
makrut lime leaves.
And that's just gonna sit
there and steep for how long?
Minimum two hours.
Now we're gonna marinate
the softshell crab
in Sriracha overnight.
We're gonna dredge it
in the potato starch
and fry it
for about a minute.
-I'm excited.
-All right, let's do this.
Got our broth ready to go.
Got my clams going in.
Let these kind of
start to open,
and then we'll add
our scallops.
Mussels will go off quick
with their little, thin shell.
Tiger prawns, tomatoes,
wide, extra-large
rice noodle --
deep fryer, 400 degrees.
Oooh!
Hi. I'm fried.
I'm crunchy.
Yeah. We're gonna go ahead and
drop our shellfish into this,
and then I'm gonna
finish the sauce.
Take our curry paste,
swirl that,
snap, crackle, pop
over our noodles,
add the softshell crab,
finish it with some
Thai micro basil.
I'm fly with my Thai.
And we are good to go.
That's gonna be hot.
That was a bold bite.
Here's my piece, my friend.
I wanted that to be great.
Okay, it's not great.
It's phenomenal.
Thank you.
I mean, that seafood couldn't
be cooked any better.
It couldn't be any fresher.
It's incredible flavor,
but it's not
beating your palate up.
It's fresh veggie,
sweet coconut,
the little touch of the fried
softshell crab on there,
and the little texture
of the fried noodle,
little kiss of the acidity
of the tomato.
I mean, it just -- the list
goes on and on and on.
Thank you.
That was nice.
You broke that down nice.
That's your song
right there, baby.
Tom Kha Gai steamers.
WOMAN:
The broth is a little sweet,
but it's also got that spice.
The fried crab is delicious.
It's like a seafood potato chip.
Crispy noodles, and they get
a little tender and chewy.
The scallops melt in your mouth.
This is not what I was expecting
when I came to Chico.
It's good, clean food.
I think a lot of people think
of Chico as this college town,
but it is becoming
a foodie destination.
Just being in
an agricultural area,
we have access to a lot of
really delicious, fresh produce
as well as fresh fish
'cause the ocean's
not terribly far away.
We're hanging out in Chico
at a joint that you probably
wouldn't expect -- a raw bar.
But when we come back,
the chef is gonna make
something else
that'll just blow our mind.
And he's bringing
Korea to NorCal.
Selling bibimbap.
When I order it,
my mouth starts watering.
Talk amongst yourselves.
We'll be right back.
After these messages.
-It's already plugged in.
-Yeah, we're...
-You guys are pros.
Not really, but we're...
[ Laughter ]
Welcome back.
Hanging out at The Rawbar
in Chico, California
with Chef Darren.
And I got to be
honest with you --
I thought, "Come on. Fresh
seafood? Is it real deal?
Trust me -- real deal.
And Agedashi Bowl
coming your way.
The menu is really diverse
Asian fusion.
You always get to experience
delicious flavors.
FIERI: Like Darren's take
on a Korean classic.
Pork belly on the bibimbap.
WOMAN: Got the egg and pork
belly, crispy rice cake.
It's a little spicy.
It's amazing.
It's kind of like dinner,
breakfast in a bowl.
We're gonna get started with
the basics of our bibimbap.
[ Speaking gibberish ]
Exactly.
We'll get our pork belly
curing.
Granulated sugar
and kosher salt.
-How long's this gonna go?
-Overnight with this.
Next step --
we're gonna braise it.
Ginger, cola...
-As in, like, a soda?
-Yeah.
...and water.
-Braise it for how long?
-Two to three hours.
-Next step?
-Our ginger-scallion sauce.
Start off
with light soy sauce.
I'm a light soy guy.
When you're cooking
with it,
you want to be able
to adjust your salt.
Exactly.
Fresh green onions,
fresh ginger root,
unseasoned rice vinegar --
same reason.
You control it.
Granulated sugar,
as I call it,
the Asian Worcestershire --
Unagi sauce.
Typically for bibimbap
is the crusty rice.
We're gonna actually make
a rice cake to fry.
First, we're gonna start off
with sushi rice,
panko rice crumbs --
that's gonna help bind it --
a little scallion.
-Go all the way with it.
-All right.
Live on the edge.
Come on!
Housemade
lemongrass syrup,
fresh garlic, salt,
fresh-ground black pepper,
use a little bit
more panko,
and this is going to sit
for a couple hours
to really let that panko
do its magic.
If Flavortown had a hockey team,
there's the puck.
-We have a kimchi sauce.
-What's in the kimchi sauce?
Granulated sugar,
fish sauce,
light soy sauce,
toasted ground habanero
and Thai chilies.
Let's assemble
this bad boy.
We got our sliced pork belly
in here browning.
A neutral oil in there,
carrots and yellow onions.
Bok choy here, and deglaze
with our kimchi sauce.
Little shaved daikon radish.
Take our rice cake, and
then we're gonna go ahead --
You got too much time
on your hands.
Look at this guy.
Nice, round
pork belly here.
We do like to add
one more component to this
for kind of the oddball
customer that comes in
and wants an egg on this.
Nobody wants an egg on top.
Daikon radish sprouts.
This is our ginger-scallion
sauce we made earlier.
Still feel like something's
missing, but voilà.
Nothing's missing.
I want to see people
chop it all up
so you get all those flavors
all blended and mixed.
I'm just following
your lead, Chef.
And I like the way
you do that.
I can imagine for folks
that enjoy that egg
running over the top of it
taking this to the next level.
But I will tell you,
my friend,
as this stands --
ginger-scallion sauce,
little fried,
crunchy rice cake
but super tender in the middle,
bok choy, carrots,
unctuous,
crispy pork belly,
and then taking the depth
of making the kimchi sauce
to really just get
that extra little punch
on top of these veggies...
it's dynamite.
Thank you.
Bibimbap.
If you're a fan of pork belly,
the sear it perfectly.
A lot better flavor than bacon.
WOMAN:
Going through layer after layer
and discovering different foods
underneath --
it's a masterpiece.
CHADDERDON:
Ribs, table 12.
I've been coming to The Rawbar
for 18 years since it opened,
and it's just been
an institution in my life.
I'm disappointed that I haven't
known you earlier,
so we got a lot of time
to make up.
That's two items
on the menu.
There's only 35 more.
Let's start cooking.
[ Laughing ]
FIERI: Coming up --
a scientist-chef power duo
in Vancouver...
I like that.
FIERI: ...making fresh catch
good for the planet...
Fin-to-tail.
FIERI:
...and great for the palate.
All the little gems in the crown
right on top of this thing.
♪♪
All right, what do you get
when you combine
a marine biologist and a chef?
No, this is not a joke,
you guys.
I'm really serious about this.
You get a funky little joint
right here on the main street
of Vancouver, Canada,
that's serving up locally and
sustainably harvested seafood.
This is The Fish Counter.
Two crispy oysters
and a bouillabaisse.
This is the place where people
who know fish come for seafood.
Your oyster Po'boy.
WOMAN: They'll tell you
what's available,
what's fresh,
what's in season.
They'll tell you the fishermen
who caught the fish,
and they'll tell you
how to cook it.
And that's just
the fish-counter side.
FIERI: That knowledge is
dished out by owner
and marine biologist
Mike McDermid.
And in the kitchen,
Chef Rob Clark
is cooking it
as fast as they can catch it.
The cod, please.
FIERI: Together, they take
their mission seriously.
We demonstrate that
you can have a local,
responsible,
sustainable seafood shop
and still stay in business.
It becomes, with our customer,
an education process.
So it's education,
conservation.
I mean, if you look at
our case, it's super minimal.
I want to try it all.
And we'd love you to
taste the Keta Salmon.
That's a fish and chips.
I've never heard of fish
and chips done with salmon.
MAN: The place is known for
its fish and chips.
I don't think anybody
does it any better.
CLARK: Two-piece salmon.
WOMAN #2:
This is unique.
You don't just get
your random whitefish.
It's one of the underdogs,
unsung heroes.
-What's kicking this off?
-Tartar sauce.
Simple, fresh ingredients.
-Regular mayo.
-Lemon juice, cornichon.
Ground-up little pickles.
-Parsley, tarragon.
-Got it.
Chopped capers,
shallots,
and a little bit
of dry dill.
This'll just improve with
a little bit of time.
Yeah, about two hours.
-Next step?
-Batter.
Up!
Batter up.
Oh, that's
an American thing.
Is that?
No, you guys play baseball.
I'm just kidding.
All-purpose flour,
rice flour,
quite a bit
of baking powder.
Quite a bit, for sure.
Cornstarch,
and a touch of salt.
Soda water, a little bit
of local beer.
You're getting the effervescence
from the beer,
the effervescence
from the soda water.
So one of the techniques
we use is
frozen stainless-steel plates
that keep the batter cold.
The colder,
the lighter and airier
it's gonna puff
when it hits the hot oil.
-Exactly.
-Love it.
And what type of salmon
is this we're gonna use?
Harrison River wild Keta
caught by the
Chehalis First Nation.
It's a meatier fish.
We're just gonna
batter this,
put it on the cold plate.
And we fry.
So, fresh-cut fries,
and what kind of potatoes
are we getting?
Local Kennebecs
from Langley.
And then some salmon
fit for a king.
Wow!
That right there --
that's got a good amount
of flavor,
not oily one bit, and you
get some great crunch.
Batter's not too much.
It's not competing
with the fish.
Tartar sauce -- that's
a nice balance right there.
Fries are legit.
Give me the rundown
on the slaw.
Kale, cabbage, rice vinegar,
and celery shoots.
Nice juxtaposition to
the salty-fried-crunchy.
Nicely done, my friend.
And a two-piece salmon.
Enjoy.
Ah! It's so good.
It has, like, the perfect crisp,
but also, like,
a softness to it.
MAN:
There's a lot of good flavor
with the tartar sauce
and the fries.
It's also highlighting
a salmon species
that isn't often
cooked with.
Which is the perfect fish
to do for fried fish.
Absolutely.
They respect the resources.
100% local.
If it's not available, even
though you love to carry it...
Don't have it.
If it's not harvested from
the responsible fishermen,
you don't carry it.
We don't have it.
Okay, here we go --
Sturgeon Banh Mi.
Does sustainability
mean that
you have to lack in flavor,
it has to lack in quality?
Oh, definitely not,
elsewise I wouldn't be here.
-Okay.
-This stuff is amazing.
One BC Bouillabaisse, please.
BC Bouillabaisse is kind of
like a fish stew.
It has some shellfish
and some other fish in there.
And then it has
a really nice garlic element.
A French classic,
but a BC version of it.
You're taking me
from fried seafood
to gently poached-in-broth
seafood.
-Yes.
-I like that.
Little bit of olive oil,
some onions, garlic,
some salt, fennel.
Love that amount of fennel.
I'm basically starting
with the harder vegetables
and moving towards
the softer.
As they'll cook down.
Peppers, bay leaves,
and some saffron.
-Let that bloom.
-Tomatoes.
It'll take about 15, 20 minutes
for this to cook down.
This is our base.
Now we go --
we cook it to order.
In the seafood tank,
you have baskets
of different shellfish.
You can't get it
any fresher than that,
unless you're pulling it
out of the sea
and you're standing on
the back of the boat.
So, we'll just get
a little bit of the base,
get some clams.
The hardest to open,
the thickest shell.
Yep.
Few mussels.
Let's talk about this garlic
puree that goes on top.
It's roasted garlic confit.
Feed in a little bit of
vegetable oil and puree it up.
I'd like to smear that
on some sourdough.
Wow.
That's a good dollop.
Yeah.
Some sablefish.
You guys call them
Alaskan black cod.
Wild northern coho salmon,
some Pacific Cod,
some sockeye, some ling.
I'm a big ling fan.
And we're gonna wait
about 30 seconds, and --
-Just enough to wake it up.
-Yep.
All the little gems in the crown
right on top of this thing.
Little bit of extra oomph.
♪♪
Mmm. There's that textural
element to veggies
and the tomatoes, which adds
this really nice bite.
Then you have
this garlic confit
that adds a real
nice body to it.
Then you have
fresh shellfish.
It's tender,
but it has a completely
different profile
than the fish does.
And then to have a nice
little variety of fish --
so simple, yet so delicious
and refined.
Oh, shut the front
and back door.
Bouillabaisse is up
for table 71.
MAN: Every bite you're taking
is something different.
It's also something fresh.
Everything orchestrated like
a little symphony of yes.
WOMAN: It really highlights
how this place
uses every part of the fish
and nothing goes to waste.
It's really
fin-to-tail cooking.
-Fin-to-tail.
-One chowder, please.
It's by far the best spot
to come and get seafood
in Vancouver.
Its reputation spread
around the world.
FIERI: We heard about
the fresh-fish case.
We heard about you
as a chef.
We heard about the sustainable
attitude and enthusiasm.
I think you've knocked both
of them out of the park.
Congrats, man.
Thank you.
So that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to FoodNetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
See you in a second.
Wha!
[ Laughter ]
I don't know.
I caught an edge on my foot.
I about came over on you.
[ Laughter ]
-What just happened?
-I don't know.