I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, I'll have more of that.
...we're rounding up
some 'round-the-world flavor...
That is the way to have it
right there, my friend.
...from a bite of Britain
in Delaware...
You want a slice?
What do you think
about that question?
[ Laughs ]
...to a legendary seafood spot
in Kauai.
This isn't, like,
the everyday fish market.
No.
Plus, real-deal Mexican
in San Diego...
I'm a fan.
I believe.
...dialing up the heat.
Every chili-head,
you got to some see this.
This is your kind of goods.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, if you've been coming to the
island of Kauai since the 1970s,
you've probably
heard of this place
or a buddy
that's worked at this place
or know people that are
huge fans of this place.
I mean, it's literally
an institution on the island.
Now, it's changed hands
quite a few times,
and the current owners
have worked here
since '95,
bought it in 2007.
This is the Hanalei Dolphin.
♪♪
Cajun ahi up
with a vegetable kebab.
The Dolphin is a local favorite.
Filet, crab legs.
We've celebrated everything
in here since we were kids.
Best fresh fish in Hawaii.
FIERI:
And owners,
Douglas and Beatrice Allen,
are tripling down
when it comes to that
straight-off-the-hook catch.
Certain sections of
the restaurant never changed.
And we added a sushi bar.
We also have
our fish market.
And Chef Nephi Takenaka's
cooking up
what their reeling in.
Teriyaki ahi, grilled,
with rice.
You should definitely try
the teriyaki tuna.
It's a house specialty.
They prepare it pink inside,
not all-the-way cooked through.
Just the right amount
of teriyaki sauce
so you don't lose
the flavor of the fish.
Alright, Chef.
I want to know about the recipe
that everybody that has been
through this restaurant tells me
about -- this teriyaki sauce.
Yeah, let's do it.
Add some oil.
Bit of garlic.
A lot of bit of garlic.
And this has been
the same recipe
from when it started
and that you've learned?
Absolutely...
Got it.
...yes, since 1970s.
Add in the cherry wine.
Water.
Soy sauce?
Soy sauce, yeah.
Don't want to get
those water pitchers
mixed up
when we're serving the table.
White sugar.
Brown sugar.
White pepper. Ginger.
Lots of ginger.
And some green onions.
And how long is this gonna
cook down for, Chef?
30 minutes.
So, we're taking
this sushi-grade ahi
that we use
on the sushi line...
Correct.
...and we're gonna make this
for the teriyaki ahi?
Yes, sir.
Alright.
Cut it into about
1/2-pound portion.
How long is it gonna go
in the marinade?
Six hours.
Oh, I'll have more of that.
So, you don't want to have
too much marinade on it
to where you lose
the flavor of the tuna...
Yes.
...but enough that
it works with it.
Absolutely.
Onto the grill -- medium rare.
That's as simple
and as clean as it comes.
Lemon and...
It's a drawn butter.
It's salted.
That's what I'm talking about
right there.
I don't get any teriyaki sauce
on the side?
Oh, no.
"You're killin' me, Smalls."
It's straight
with the drawn butter.
When I cut into this,
it is perfectly seared.
It is literally cold in the
center -- exactly how I like it.
Little bit of rice to it.
And the butter has
that little kick of salt...
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
...a little bit of the fat.
That is the way to have it
right there, my friend.
You weren't lying
on that one.
I wouldn't have done it.
Glad you like it.
Here's the thing
that I'm happiest about.
You didn't take
that delicious piece of ahi
and hammer the marinade
all the way through it.
Without question, you really
get the taste of fish.
I can see why this has been
on the menu that long.
Well done.
Thank you so much.
Teriyaki ahi up.
It's perfectly cooked
and seasoned
and has that
juicy tenderness inside.
I don't think it needs
the butter.
It's that good.
But with the butter,
it definitely gives it
a little something special.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
Teriyaki ahi
is really good.
How about yourself?
I love the sushi here.
This reigns supreme
as sushi in this area?
Because once you have
the fish market
with the sushi bar,
you can't beat that.
This isn't, like,
the everyday fish market.
No.
So, you're bringing whole fish
in and breaking them down?
That's correct.
This is about a 200-pound
local ahi.
Yellowfin?
Yellowfin.
I'm quick.
It's a monster.
FIERI:
But it's turning bite-sized
in this Hawaiian classic.
Two avocado poke bowls.
It's the most special poke bowl
I've ever had in my entire life.
The perfect blend of spices,
of fresh, fresh fish, and rice.
If you're an avocado lover,
this is your dish.
Why aren't you cutting?
Well, Jared's one of the
best cutters we got here.
He's better at it than I am.
[ Laughs ]
For the big 200-pounder
that's in there,
how long will it take you
to break that down?
2-3 minutes.
Seriously?
I almost said, "Hours."
Why doesn't Jared have
a cape like Superman?
Cuts through it
like it's butter.
Now that we've processed
our ahi,
we're gonna be ready to assemble
our ahi-avocado poke.
Okay, Chef,
let's see this.
Avocado.
Some white onion.
Little bit of sea asparagus.
Nice, crunchy,
just a little touch of salt.
And then we got a little
kukui nut and green onion.
And then we got
some Hawaiian salt.
That's about as fresh
as it comes.
Wasabi aioli on top.
And then some unagi sauce.
People can get this to go.
They can get it here,
out of the market.
Absolutely.
They can get it
at the sushi bar.
at the table.
You can get it
everywhere.
It just wrecks it
for everybody...
when you have poke in Hawaii,
how night-and-day different
it is
from the rest of the world.
We take a lot of pride in our
local fish here, for sure.
The little sea-asparagus crunch,
creamy avocado,
sharpness of the onion
with the tenderness
and the creaminess
of the ahi...
And you know what
the other little kicker is?
As you're biting down,
you got this soft texture,
and you get this little
explosion of that sea salt.
It's really good,
local salt.
I can't eat it
fast enough.
Glad you like it.
Mmm!
Like it?
Can I try the sesame one?
Absolutely.
Oh, nothing,
just moving the spoon.
When people come in, you give
them a little taster like this?
We do.
We give them a little bite
with that.
That's the wrong thing
to tell me, buddy.
How many sticks you got?
All the sticks you need,
my friend.
That one was awesome.
Ahi-avocado poke bowl
for table 7.
It's delicious.
I make the mistake of eating
the ahi so fast.
WOMAN:
Flavors are just awesome.
The wasabi gives it
a little kick.
FIERI:
There's a lot of great
poke on the island.
The way they're doing it --
what makes it so different?
It's just local-style,
family-style.
I don't think it can get
any fresher
unless we were eating it
on the boat.
Exactly.
There you go.
Next best thing.
If anybody ever asks me,
"Where should I go
when I come to Kauai,"
I say, "The Dolphin."
It's legendary.
You're in paradise, for sure.
When I first cruised by,
I thought to myself,
"I wonder if that's
a tourist spot."
When you have a fish market
out the back --
not a lot of tourists
who can come and buy fresh fish.
I mean, after two days,
it's a stinky souvenir.
[ Laughs ]
Absolutely, yes.
When I get in here, and I see
the attention to detail...
Really nice.
Thank you so much.
FIERI: Up next...
Back on the mainland,
we're hitting a mom-and-pop
Mexican spot in San Diego...
The real deal.
...delivering
a surprise combo...
This is a new one.
I've never seen a chili relleno
in a burrito.
...and a knockout dish
with a fiery punch.
Good luck.
That's not what you're
supposed to say, Chuy.
It's like, "Bon appetit," or
something, but not, "Good luck."
♪♪
You know, on "Triple D,"
I don't know
what's more amazing.
Is it the food or is it the
stories of these restaurants?
And I got to believe that the
stories of the restaurants
really influence
the way the food tastes.
So I'm here in San Diego
to check out a joint
where a young married couple
took their entire life savings
that they had set for a house
to open their own restaurant.
It's the American dream.
This is Chuy's Taco Shop.
GAYTAN:
Two minutes in the fryer.
Chuy's does it right.
This place is my favorite
for Mexican food.
SERVER:
Chilaquiles, green.
There's a million taco shops
in this city.
Yeah.
And this place is getting
recognition, why?
FIERI:
And that work ethic is how
Chuy Gaytan and his brother,
Armando, like to roll --
first,
moving from Mexico
to finish school...
How long have you been
in the States?
10 years.
...then eventually,
along with Chuy's wife, Marcela,
hitting their goal of opening
a restaurant
serving their family recipes.
The spices, the way that it's
presented is just like home.
Chuy's burrito.
Chuy's burrito's awesome.
The carnitas is great.
And the unique thing is
the chili rellenos that's in it.
So, my buddies
Josh and Billy here --
have you ever had
a chili relleno in a burrito?
I have not.
What do you think?
I love it.
Let's get after this.
Pleasurely.
Some carnitas
for the Chuy burrito.
Did your mom make carnitas
at home when you were a kid?
Yeah.
Yeah, my father.
Lard.
Orange juice.
Salt.
Garlic.
Beer.
And the onion.
How long is this gonna go, Chuy?
Three hours.
So, while that cooks, we're
gonna make the chili relleno.
The chili relleno.
We start off
with the fresh peppers.
And then
put them in the fryer.
Put them in the fryer?
Yes.
Just enough to --
They start peeling.
Because if you make
the chili relleno
with the skin on,
it's just too tough.
Exactly.
You got to bite through it.
Just make a little hole.
And what kind of cheese
is this?
How many pieces of cheese?
Three or four.
I'm gonna be done.
You got to hurry up, Chuy.
Come on.
Now we go to the flour?
Just flour up.
Next up?
Make the batter.
Egg whites.
So, we're gonna make
a meringue first.
Flour.
And the yolks.
The whole thing.
Don't worry.
All of it?
Yeah, yeah.
God, you're an animal,
Chuy.
Nice and light.
Float it in there.
Beautiful.
Once it's done...
Make the burrito.
Okay.
Carnita.
Very strange.
I've never seen a chili relleno
in a burrito.
Throw on the tortilla.
[ Whistles ]
The guacamole sauce.
And wrap it.
[ Laughs ]
Chuy, I know
it's hard to believe --
I've had a few burritos
in my day.
[ Laughs ]
I've had
peppers and onions.
But having the chili relleno and
the texture inside of a burrito,
I've never had.
This is a great way
to incorporate it.
I see why
you call it the Chuy.
You don't look like you eat
any of them.
Oh, come on.
You get a lot of chili flavor,
a good balance of meat.
It's not overloaded with meat.
Nice, fresh pico de gallo.
Mmm!
Scratch-made.
The real deal.
Delicious.
-Thank you.
-Chuy's burrito here.
The carnitas was
cooked perfectly.
Chili relleno
has a good texture.
Every bite that you get
is really, really nice.
SERVER:
Second rolled taco ready.
San Diego is the mecca of
Mexican food outside of Mexico,
so there's a lot of competition.
MAN:
Everyone tries to claim
authentic Mexican food,
but I drive through
a few hundred of them
just to come here.
I actually live about
25 minutes away,
but I come over here
just for the food.
FIERI:
And if you're searching
for spice, you're in luck.
Shrimp a la Diabla plate.
MAN:
The Shrimp a la Diabla
is definitely one of
the spiciest dishes I've had.
Just as the name implies,
it's a little spice
from the Devil.
MAN #2: There's a lot
of shrimp on there.
Plus, there's rice and beans.
It's a good dish.
What else are we
gonna make, Chuy?
Mexican rice.
For the...
Let's fry the rice.
You're gonna fry it?
Yes.
This is a new one.
So, not fry it in a pan
with a little bit of oil --
you're gonna go
to the fryer fryer.
Yes.
Huh.
This changes the texture
dramatically.
It's his place.
It says "Chuy" on the door.
He can do what he wants.
Next?
Butter.
Boy, we are just throwing it
all out the window here.
Bell pepper, carrots,
and onion.
Water.
Salt.
Garlic.
And the rice.
Chuy-style.
Tomato sauce.
With that rice being fried
like that,
the rice is gonna be
nice and light and fluffy.
And how long is
this gonna go, Chuy?
About 20 minutes.
So, next, the diabla sauce.
Yes.
Sannam pepper.
Sannam?
It's from India.
What's a kid from Mexico doing
using a pepper from India?
You want to try to get
a couple more in there?
[ Laughs ] No.
Garlic.
Black pepper.
For some reason, this looks
like it's gonna be hot.
Salt.
Butter.
And water.
Puree it to death.
And then cook it.
For how long, Chuy?
Five minutes.
Well, this right here is gonna
peel the paint off the wall.
And how are we gonna
cook the shrimp?
With the butter.
Diabla sauce.
Looks like mole.
Hot and ready.
Good luck.
That's not what you're
supposed to say, Chuy.
It's like, "Bon appetit,"
or something,
but not,
"Good luck."
Enjoy.
Yeah, "Enjoy."
♪♪
Really good.
The rice did exactly
what I thought it would do --
bloomed up nice.
The shrimp is cooked
perfectly --
just got a little crust on them,
didn't hit them with the sauce.
Straight from the Devil.
That's one of the hottest things
we've ever had on "Triple D."
But when you're gonna call it
The Devil's Shrimp,
the Diabla...
Diabla.
...you better bring the heat.
That's got the heat.
Warning.
How do you say "pain"
in Spanish?
Dolor.
If you like spicy food,
come on down to casa dolor.
This comes with ice cream,
I hope.
Every chili-head,
you got to come see this.
This is your kind of goods.
Thank you so much.
SERVER: Shrimp a la Diabla
plate ready.
It has a smoky touch to the
spice -- absolutely delicious.
MAN #2:
It starts off sweet,
and the next thing you know,
you're sweating.
This is Tommy the AD
and sometimes director
in the world
of "Guy's Grocery Games."
How we doing, buddy?
Really, really good.
On the Tommy scale of 1 to 10,
where would you put --
About a 7.
My scale is very high.
But he keeps going, folks.
Carne asada fries -- ready.
MAN: Food here is always
gonna be amazing.
Just like Mom made.
MAN #2:
The sizes of portions are great,
but really, what sticks out
is just the freshness
of the ingredients
and the family atmosphere
when you walk in the door.
The fact that you were able
to save the money
and open up a restaurant
is remarkable.
That's what the American
dream's about.
I'm a fan.
I believe.
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up...
A legit English pub
in Wilmington, Delaware...
I just want that bite
right there.
...owned by a bloke
with a jamming past...
That's how they do it
in the rock 'n' roll world.
...bringing stand-out
English staples Stateside.
You're gonna have to pry this
out of my hand.
♪♪
You know, I think all rock stars
want to be restaurant owners
and all restaurants owners
want to be rock stars.
So I got a great one for you.
I'm here outside of Wilmington,
Delaware.
Now, this is where a record
promoter toured
all over the world with
the big bands, the huge names.
And finally, he said,
"That's it.
I'm getting off the road.
I want a taste of my flavors
from home."
So he opened his own joint.
This is Stoney's Pub.
Shepherd pie.
Makes me feel like I'm back
in London.
[ British accent ]
My goodness.
It's an authentic English pub
with an authentic Englishman.
And to have you here
is an honor.
FIERI: Yep.
Owner Mike Stone has come
across the pond
to rock
some hard-core pub food.
Yorkshire sandwich
with cheddar -- pick it up.
FIERI: But before he was
in the restaurant biz,
this dude was eating
up the music world.
You've worked with
Bob Marley.
Doobie Brothers, I traveled
with, Fleetwood Mac...
I was able to travel all over
America, go to any restaurant.
None of them served
a decent fish and chips.
None of them knew
how to make Yorkshire pudding.
So I said, "If I'm gonna retire
and eat the food I like,
I'm gonna have to
make it myself."
Or at least,
recruit someone else to do it.
I ate a meal.
I asked, "I'd like
to meet the chef."
So I went back
to the kitchen.
I met Thomas Darson,
who is my head chef.
You went and poached him
out of another restaurant?
Yeah. Well, how else do you
do these things?
That's how they do it
in the rock 'n' roll world.
Yeah, it's coming along.
It's like an extended
family now.
Mike, Thomas --
they will not deviate
from the authenticity
of the recipes.
Fish and chips up.
I'm a regular traveler
to England.
This is the best fish
and chips I've ever had.
What makes great
fish and chips?
Everything's fresh --
your batter,
your fish, your oil.
So you make a batter a few
times throughout the week?
Few times
throughout the day.
Set him up for that one.
Now we're gonna make
the batter.
We got flour. Salt.
Pepper.
And where did you
get the recipe from?
From Mike Stone.
And where did Mike
get the recipe from?
From his mum.
His mum.
Oh, look at you,
speaking the language now.
A little water.
Mix it all together.
You want that vinegar in now?
Yes, sir.
And there's our batter.
Fresh Alaskan cod.
Now we're gonna dust our fish
in flour.
And it's ready to batter.
So, now over the the fryer?
Yep, for 11 minutes.
Alright, Chef.
We're gonna make tartar sauce.
Mayo.
I didn't think there was
tartar sauce in England.
You're right, Guy.
There's no tartar sauce
in England.
We have to do this behind
Stoney's back.
Initially, we had to do it
behind his back.
Stoney!
How about that?
Relish.
A little Worcestershire.
Old Bay.
Alright.
So that's done.
And how about the fries?
What are we doing for the chips?
I've cut the fries.
Soak them in the water.
Fry it all for seven minutes.
Back in the tub.
Fresh water.
Okay.
Fry them for service.
You got it.
Let's see it.
I like to put the chips
on first.
Then that way, you could build
a little mound
to rest your fish on.
♪♪
Flaky, tender fish --
super-fresh.
Right.
The batter is
nice and crunchy.
That nice, big fry --
great crunch.
I don't like fish and chips
'cause typically,
it's frozen fish,
too much batter.
Mm-hmm.
If this is what fish and chips
was every time
I was getting fish and chips,
I'd eat more fish
and chips, man.
Represent.
Thank you.
Fish and chips.
[ British accent ] The fish
is nice and flaky inside.
The chips --
they're nice and crunchy.
I don't eat much
fried food.
I always get this.
And it's the real deal?
Oh, yeah.
Right. Oh.
[ Both laugh ]
MAN: It's a great place to come
and just hang out,
and Mike's got
some great stories
from his days on the road.
The name Stoney came from
my first meeting
with Bob Marley
and his manager.
He said, "Bob, this
is Mike Stone.
He's gonna be working with us
on the tour."
Marley looks at me.
He goes, "Stone.
Stoney!
Come with me, Stoney."
I would expect him to have
a little-different accent.
[ Laughing ]
Yeah.
You have all Stoney's
memorabilia
from the music days --
the records.
And it's this friendly,
great atmosphere.
FIERI: I figured
if I came to Stoney's
that he's gonna have
great fish and chips,
but the one thing
I really got to have...
Roast beef
and Yorkshire pudding?
Yorkshire pudding.
Beef and Yorkshire.
It's basically this shell
of bread crust,
which is my favorite
part of bread.
It's made the British way,
and it's amazing.
We come back --
Yorkshire pudding.
But I will finish this first.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
Okay, so, tell me about
the fish and chips.
How does this guy do?
I've never seen anybody
take a bite that big
before an interview question.
[ Laughs ]
Welcome back.
"Triple D" is hanging out
in Wilmington, Delaware
at the famous Stoney's.
It is a authentic,
genuine British pub.
When your mother says
it's a shepherd's pie,
you call it
a shepherd's pie, mate.
Yes.
Mike Stone is the owner,
and he hails from England.
FIERI:
And he's got Chef Thomas
dishing up real-deal U.K. grub.
Yorkshire pudding.
A Yorkshire pudding
is actually a batter baked
in a very hot fat --
very similar to a popover.
Normally a Sunday afternoon
lunch or evening dinner --
roast beef
and Yorkshire pudding.
Alright, let's see it.
DARSON:
We're gonna make our seasoning
for the roast beef.
This is a top round.
Garlic and paprika.
Paprika.
Onion.
Chili flake.
Black pepper.
Some salt.
Mix that all up.
Rub it down.
And what temp and how long?
275° for about four
to five hours.
Next, what are we into?
We're gonna make the batter
for our Yorkshire pudding.
Flour.
White pepper.
Salt.
Some eggs in.
And then our milk.
We start by heating up suet.
So, beef fat.
Yes, sir.
Boy, those look brand-new, like
you just got them yesterday.
Pour it in there.
Then slam it back in the oven.
475°, 40 minutes.
Alright,
Chef, game plan.
We got top round here.
This is our gravy pan.
We're gonna add
a little beef stock
and a little cornstarch
to thicken.
Then we take our top round,
nice slice here,
and then we go
right into the gravy.
You want a slice?
What do you think about
that question?
[ Laughs ]
Perfect medium-rare,
great piece of meat.
Here we go.
Mashed potatoes.
Cabbage.
Beef.
Where's the pudding?
Oh, my friend.
Here's your pudding.
Roast beef and Yorkshire.
That's how we do it.
♪♪
That's all I want
right there.
I just want that.
I want that bite right there.
[ Laughs ]
I mean, the key is --
I wouldn't like it with filet.
I wouldn't like it
with New York.
It's got to be top round,
got to have a little chew to it.
That's all
I'm talking about.
Mmm!
I've seen more bad popovers
than I've seen good ones,
and that right there --
you're gonna have to
pry this out of my hand.
When we first opened,
Stoney would come down
for dinner,
and he would sit
in this back room
and eat it
with syrup on it.
Back there?
Give me my plate.
With his
Yorkshire pudding.
And everybody would be
doing their thing,
and he would still
be back there eating...
I'll be right back!
...'cause he was afraid somebody
was gonna ask him for stuff.
[ Mouthful ] Keep quiet.
[ Laughs ]
Roast beef
and Yorkshire.
The Yorkshire pudding --
nice and crispy on the outside
but so moist on the inside.
MAN:
The roast beef is tender.
You can cut it with a fork.
[ Normal voice ] Have you had
Yorkshire pudding before?
My mom used to make it.
Like this?
It tastes just like Mom's.
Got to get some chips down.
If you're looking for a slice of
Britain in Delaware, this is it.
Get a lot of big flavor, but you
do it with a lot of enthusiasm
and a lot of personality,
and you own it.
Thank you for coming.
Watch out for this guy.
You're gonna put on weight.
[ Laughs ]
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry,
there's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
Tommy, you are now dri-- you
are sweating behind your ear.
Can you just turn
for a second?
[ Laughs ]
Oh.