Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out, looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
[rock music playing]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
This trip--
Holy moly.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Triple D's in all caps--
as it capital cities.
That sounds fun.
I'll try that.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Like Juneau, Alaska,
for a real deal taste of Italy.
Did that just make you as
hungry as it should have?
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Amped-up
brunch in the DC of Canada.
This is absolutely
a destination.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And an
old-school spot in Richmond,
Virginia--
It may appear to
be your typical deli.
This is as far from
it as I've seen.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --putting
out show-stopping new releases.
This is like I've
been going to all
the movies in black and white.
And then today, I went to IMAX.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Diners,
Drive-ins, and Dives."
[rock music playing]
Now on Triple D, I
think I've seen them all.
I've seen the delicatessens.
I've seen the diners.
I've seen the sandwich shops.
I've seen the corner stores.
You name it.
But I'm here in
Richmond, Virginia,
where this couple has
resurrected an institution.
They've brought it back using
their own little funky style.
This is Perly's Restaurant
and Delicatessen.
[inaudible] and beef knish.
There's nothing
I've ever tasted
or been to that's like Perly's.
The Perlstein for you.
This is nothing like your
regular delicatessen or diner.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): That's
because Rochelle and Kevin
Roberts are mixing his
master cooking with the food
her bubby used to make.
I'm Jewish.
OK.
And there was nowhere
to get this food.
Where'd you get
all the recipes?
Family recipes that
have been tweaked,
collaborations
between the two of us.
They have a lot of
items on their menus
that you're not going
to find in other places.
For instance, the potato
and duck pierogies.
Potato and duck pierogies.
GUY FIERI: You ever
have pierogies before?
These pierogies are better
than any other pierogies
that you can find.
Creamy, hardy, moist.
All of a sudden, he's
taking over the show.
He's starting to give the
whole description of it.
I mean, I just asked him if
he'd had pierogies before.
How are we starting
this thing off?
We're going to make
some pierogi dough.
GUY FIERI: OK.
KEVIN ROBERTS:
Eggs, sour cream--
That's the way I always
make my pierogi dough.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Water
and salt. AP flour.
GUY FIERI: How long are we
going to let this mix up?
For a few minutes, and
then we wrap it up and let
it rest in the refrigerator.
All right, so now
we're going to make
the cure for the duck legs.
White sugar, brown sugar,
sumac, and some kosher salt.
So, breakfast and lunch?
Breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
And you're taking all the
time to make confit duck legs?
Why not?
GUY FIERI: Does she
let you go home?
I mean, or just stay here?
She likes it when
I'm home, actually.
Yes.
You didn't have to say it
in a sultry voice like that.
Crushed juniper berry,
raw garlic, fresh thyme.
Put the duck legs
on top of this.
And then we'll
reverse the order.
And we do it again?
Yup.
The garlic and then the juniper.
How many days are
on your calendar?
Just the seven.
How many hours?
60.
60 hours a day?
That's what I figured
you were working.
Refrigerate it
overnight, and then we'll
cook them in the schmaltz.
The almighty schmaltz.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Two
to three hours.
What are we on to now?
Now we're going to
make a roast tomato
ketchup, which is going
to go into the sauce
for the final dish.
Going in the sauce.
Roma tomatoes,
and chopped garlic,
dried oregano, some dried basil.
GUY FIERI: Salt and pepper.
And roast these
off at what temp?
KEVIN ROBERTS: 350-degree
oven for about an hour.
Put it in a container
with tomato paste,
and puree it until smooth.
OK, chef.
Now we're going to make the
filling for the pierogies.
Boiled potatoes, green onions,
some of the duck leg confit,
mixed peppercorn blend,
kosher salt. Mash it around.
Going to add a little bit
of that reserved duck fat.
So this whole
process is by hand?
And then we haven't even
got into the rolling
out of the dough.
- That is correct.
Oh, my goodness.
And you don't have a sheeter?
I do not have a sheeter.
I'm going to get you
one for your birthday.
When's your birthday?
My birthday was Monday.
Oh, I missed it.
Sorry.
[laughter]
Maybe at least a bigger
rolling pin, huh?
That come with an
Easy Bake Oven?
We'll cut our dough.
Brush it with a little slurry
of cornstarch and water.
Slurry up.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Pierogi filling.
GUY FIERI: How are we
cooking these from here?
KEVIN ROBERTS: They go into
a boiling pot of water.
All of this activity going
for one item on the menu?
That is correct.
You're a busy man.
So we're going to start with
duck fat, pierogies, shiitake
button mushrooms.
The ketchup that we made.
KEVIN ROBERTS: I like
to char the ketchup.
Oh, me, too.
Always.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Cooked mirepoix.
Duck stock, cover,
and let it reduce.
What do we do now?
Wait.
OK, good talk.
All right.
Voila.
And we top it off with a
little chive sour cream.
This is like
"Pierogi-- the Movie."
[cinematic music playing]
I don't know that the word
"pierogi" describes this.
It's like calling
my Camaro a car.
It's a vintage hot rod.
Great duck-- the
duck jus reduction
that the pierogi soaks up.
The vegetables, the mushrooms--
the little kiss to that
roasted tomato sauce.
This is like I've
been going to all
the movies in black and white.
And then today, I went to IMAX.
That's dynamite.
Thank you.
Potato and duck
pierogies for you.
The filling's really
creamy, and it pairs
nicely with the tomato sauce.
This is not how
they normally come.
- Correct.
- This is like pierogi meal.
You're aware of that?
- I am.
- Promise?
- Promise.
Look at the camera.
Say, "I promise."
I promise.
OK, I got it on tape.
Need a cup of
matz, chicken entr e.
Was this a deli before
you guys got here?
KEVIN ROBERTS: Yes.
ROCHELLE ROBERTS: It's
been here since 1961.
It's had a few
iterations since then.
And we of bringing
it back to its roots.
So the tile on the wall?
ROCHELLE ROBERTS: Not original.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Not original.
GUY FIERI: Wallpaper?
Anything?
The ceiling?
- I did it.
- You did it all yourself?
- Did it.
Because behind
every great chef,
there's someone that
knows how to lay tile
and do plumbing and electrical.
Perly's used to sort of be a
greasy hole-in-the-wall diner.
Kevin's made it sort
of like a modern diner.
Really beautiful.
If we were going to do
one more completely wreck it
for me dish, what would it be?
Jewish egg rolls.
The Jewish egg rolls
are one of my favorites.
The twist they put on
it here is amazing.
It's always like a Reuben
wrapped up in an egg roll.
When we come back--
Jewish egg rolls.
Here we go.
5, 4, 3, 8, and a
1, 2, a 1, 2, 3.
Welcome back.
Triple D hanging out in
Richmond, Virginia at Perly's--
old deli from the day.
And given new life
by husband and wife
team Kevin and Rochelle Roberts.
Kevin has really taken the
concept of a Jewish diner
and made it a little
bit more global.
I mean, like
with the egg rolls.
The Jewish egg rolls.
It's like an egg roll
meets a Reuben sandwich.
I inhaled it.
GUY FIERI: What are we into?
This is going to be
one of the components
of the Jewish egg roll.
Corned beef, bay leaf, all
spice berries, cinnamon,
mustard seed, whole
coriander, mixed peppercorn,
garlic, cloves, crushed
red pepper, mirepoix.
GUY FIERI: Got it.
KEVIN ROBERTS: All this will
get covered with the water.
GUY FIERI: And how are we
going to let this roast?
Three, four hours.
Five, six?
It all depends on the
size of the brisket.
Don't show off
that you can count.
Now we're going
to make the kishka.
It's going to be the
binder for our egg roll.
GUY FIERI: OK.
Minced red onion, shredded
carrots, Yukon gold potato.
GUY FIERI: OK.
Sweat this in oil.
Halfway through we're going
to add chopped garlic.
Once all the veggies have
sweated into our mixing bowl,
quick rolled oats, some
matzo meal, paprika,
coriander, cumin,
and chili powder,
black pepper, kosher
salt, pastrami.
We actually patty this.
GUY FIERI: All right, chef.
So now we're going to make
the filling for the egg rolls.
Corned beef and some pastrami.
Going to give it a few
pulses, and then into the bowl
with our kishka, sauerkraut.
We'll take our
egg-roll wrappers,
brush them with a little
of the cornstarch slurry.
We have our mix.
And then roll up our egg roll.
Well done.
This go down in the fryer?
KEVIN ROBERTS: Yes, sir.
GUY FIERI: And what are
we serving this with?
Amba sauce.
A-who-ba-ha?
KEVIN ROBERTS: It's a Middle
Eastern pickled mango sauce.
Just what I
expected to get here
with my pastrami
corned beef egg roll.
Start with a little
vegetable oil, ginger,
coriander, crushed red chili.
I think he's
just trying to show
off all the ingredients he has.
And turmeric, brown sugar,
kosher salt, lemon juice,
honey.
Gone.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Water,
garlic, white wine vinegar.
And the elephant
in the room, please?
KEVIN ROBERTS: Mango.
All right.
Let this cook down and pur e it?
KEVIN ROBERTS: That's right.
GUY FIERI: Here we go.
Plate them with
the amba sauce.
And we make a honey
mustard schmaltz.
And they always come with
two football-sized egg rolls?
Yes, sir.
If it was just all corned
beef, pastrami, or all
sauerkraut, it'd be too much.
The kishka in the middle
is a great balance.
You get the creaminess
of the potato.
You get a little bit of
the bite of the vegetable.
The amba sauce got
some punch, buddy.
We've got Middle
Eastern chutney.
A lot of power behind it.
KEVIN ROBERTS: Yeah.
You see this cute
little thing on the menu
that says Jewish egg roll.
That sounds fun.
I'll try that.
It's way beyond that--
far beyond that.
Thank you.
The Jewish egg rolls.
It's so tender.
This is delicious.
The sauce is nice and
tangy, with a little bit
of sweetness of the honey.
We've got a Reuben
wearing creamy slaw,
a Jewbano wearing fries.
Everything on the menu
is great-- all of it.
I'll be back later this week.
It may appear to
be your typical deli.
This is as far from
it as I've seen.
Nicely done, my friend.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Up next in Juno--
All day long.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Legit
pasta with an Alaskan edge.
This is the kind of thing
that people are looking for.
GUY FIERI: And fired up pie
that tastes as good as it looks.
I don't know to eat it
or take a picture of it.
[rock music playing]
I've said it once,
and I'll say it again.
You've got to slow down
and take a look around.
I'm here in Juneau, Alaska.
And every other day,
thousands of people
get off those cruise ships.
And they walk right by
this funky little joint.
Where the chef, who's
worked through the ranks
and studied a
little bit in Italy,
has opened up a joint
where he's scratch-making,
hand-making, just about
everything on the menu.
It's Alaskan food with
an Italian influence.
This is In Bocca Al Lupo.
Thunder Dome for B4.
If you want really
amazing Italian food,
like this is the place to go.
Homemade pasta.
Homemade pizza dough.
Going in with two Salsiccias.
You can tell in his style
of cooking is not from here.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Yeah, it's actually
a little something Beau
Schooler brought back from
his culinary training in Italy.
What does the name mean?
It means "into
the wolf's mouth."
It means good luck.
My goodness, I'm
learning Italian.
So you do wood-fired pizza.
What else?
Fresh pasta, our
own charcuterie.
In the summertime, where
kind of more seafood-focused.
King crab pappardelle for 25.
The king crab pappardelle?
It's hard to stop
eating, that's for sure.
Chunks of big, meaty, juicy
Alaskan wild-caught king crab.
And the pasta is perfectly al
dente every time you have it.
It's heaven on earth.
What are we going to make?
King crab pappardelle.
Let's get into it.
We've got to make the
pappardelle noodles.
Low gluten flour, egg
yolks, olive oil, sea salt.
You making all
the pasta in-house?
BEAU SCHOOLER: We make
all the pasta in-house.
We always have a gnocchi.
I'll have the ja-naki.
I love g-nochi.
Gih-no-chee.
Gin-oo-chee.
I got to knead it
'til it's smooth.
Let it rest.
Roll with a sheeter.
BEAU SCHOOLER:
Sprinkle semolina on.
GUY FIERI: Cut it by hand.
BEAU SCHOOLER: Yup.
All right.
What do we got to do, Beau?
We've got to basically
make like a seafood bisque.
And that's our pasta sauce.
GUY FIERI: OK.
Got clove, green
peppercorns, bay leaf.
We got to grind that all up.
Combine it with sweet
paprika, ginger,
cinnamon, sweet
Calabrian chili powder,
star anise, allspice, cardamom.
Cardamom?
BEAU SCHOOLER: Mustard.
There's our spice.
Something got my tongue.
Is that from the
green peppercorn?
It's that or the cinnamon.
GUY FIERI: OK, what
are we doing next?
Olive oil.
Break down our king crab legs.
Then we've got a
crab shells, here.
Garlic--
Got it.
Carrots, onion,
leeks, fennel, celery,
and ginger, and then thyme.
We cook all that down, and
we add in tomato paste.
Copious amounts.
BEAU SCHOOLER: White wine.
GUY FIERI: You glaze it.
Lemon juice, fish
sauce seasoning.
GUY FIERI: Good amount of that.
BEAU SCHOOLER: Cover
it with crushed ice.
You gotta explain
this ice game to me.
It just allows that
broth to like build
up real slowly and gently.
And then by the time
it's all melted,
it's going to simmer
for maybe 30 minutes.
So we get a ton of flavor.
I've never seen it.
Well, there you go.
Come to Alaska.
We do things cold.
I would-- he was
waiting to say that--
I wasn't.
That just popped out.
--to say that the entire time.
Well, after this
simmers, we're going
to blend it and then strain it.
We've going to
pappardelle noodles.
Throw in our bisque base.
GUY FIERI: Beautiful noodles.
BEAU SCHOOLER:
Throw in some crab.
You're generous.
BEAU SCHOOLER:
Lemon creme fraiche.
GUY FIERI: Gorgeous.
Finish it off with this sorrel
that our buddies are growing.
Delicious.
The bisque is really nice
and light and refreshing.
The crab is not tough.
The pasta is the
heart of the dish.
It is super-tender.
And the key is
the creme fraiche.
Two of my favorite things--
crab bisque in a pasta dish.
Outstanding.
King crab pappardelle
over here for you.
It is amazing.
It's creamy and it's light.
When you see fresh king crab
on a menu, you have to have it.
Walking in, two meatballs.
He's always
working and evolving
to make his product better.
With his background
in culinary from Italy,
pizza is a big part of it.
The Salsiccia
pizza is really good.
Working a Salsiccia for 15.
Fresh mozzarella,
roasted red onions,
and homemade fennel sausage.
So you've never had
it before, I can tell.
Once or twice.
All right.
So what are we
going to do first?
BEAU SCHOOLER: We're going
to mill our Alaskan wheat
for our pizza dough.
GUY FIERI: You'll sift it.
Cool water, the
fresh-milled wheat,
a high-gluten flour, and yeast.
We mix all that together.
And then we let it
sit for about an hour.
Let the yeast bloom.
BEAU SCHOOLER: And then
we'll add in salt--
four minutes on medium.
GUY FIERI: Let it proof.
BEAU SCHOOLER: Overnight.
Portion it, and then it's got to
sit out for at least two hours.
GUY FIERI: Got it.
We're going to make
our Italian sausage.
We've got pork shoulder, fennel
seed, coriander, sweet paprika,
oregano, Calabrian chili powder,
sea salt, sugar, curing salt.
GUY FIERI: OK.
And then we'll grind it.
We've got a little bit of cold
water, some red wine vinegar,
and then we just bake it
off, let it cool in walk-in.
And then we will
set up for service.
GUY FIERI: Just to make
it easier to work with?
Yeah.
We're going to make our mozz.
Curd, sea salt,
190-degree water.
It's a little bit different
than your bath water.
So we'll just drain off
this initial really hot water.
And we're going to add
more water to stretch it.
Look how beautiful that is.
It's hotter than heck.
BEAU SCHOOLER: Shape it
into our little mozz balls.
Float it off.
Look at that.
Just that little pillow.
Good amount of salt.
Just enough chew.
Look at that stretch.
All day long.
Did that just make you as
hungry as it should have?
BEAU SCHOOLER: We've got
our pizza dough, here.
GUY FIERI: Gentle,
tender, ready to rock.
Our pizza sauce--
California tomatoes,
olive oil, sea salt.
That's it.
Sausage that we just made.
Roasted red onion, mozz.
So very
Neapolitan-style-- minimal.
In the oven 750, 800--
two minutes.
Look at that.
Gorgeous.
Love all the char.
So we got this
garlic oil, here.
And then sea salt,
and here we go.
I don't know to eat it
or take a picture of it.
Beautiful crust.
Crust is the bomb, bro.
That little kick of
the ground wheat.
Sweet cheese and the acidity
on the fat of the sausage,
mixed with a little
bit of that, will char.
That's the money bite.
And each bite's a
little bit different.
Time out.
Thank you.
And Salsiccia pizza.
The wood fire brings a
nice flavor to the pizza.
The sausage of the
pizza is fantastic.
The rich, fatty flavor-- it goes
against the acid of the tomato
and the creaminess
of the cheese.
Ricotta gnocchi.
Never disappoints
to come in here.
It's just my spot.
You're making great food.
You're making it
very approachable.
This is the kind of thing
that people are looking for.
You guys are going to love this.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Coming
up, a tiny spot in Ottawa,
Canada.
I'm in the service station.
Now I'm in the prep station.
I'm over in the delivery area.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Serving up big-time breakfast,
lunch, and brunch.
Look at that.
[music playing]
I'm here in Ottawa,
Canada in an area
known as Centertown to check
out a joint with a great story.
So this guy starts as
a part-time line cook.
He eventually works
his way up to chef
and then buys the couple
out that owns the place.
Now, it is a small--
S-M-ALL-- joint, but I
hear the flavor is big.
This is Jax.
Compote's going down.
Taste is what matters, and
their food here is amazing.
Classy eggs Benny.
Homestyle brunch place that
kind of feels like your friends
work here.
Ben's got tons
of unique dishes.
He takes things
to the next level.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
'Cause Chef
Ben Breitler's
creativity hasn't been
cramped by his lack of space.
Wait a second.
I'm in the service station.
Now I'm in the prep station.
I'm over in the delivery area.
Yeah, it's tiny, but it works.
We try and get
everything locally
sourced-- cheese, meats.
Make all our bread
in-house-- little batches.
And we do a lot
of burgers here?
- Yeah.
- Where?
BEN BREITLER: We can do
one burger at a time.
Hurt my head.
You're hurting my head.
BEN BREITLER: Cheese
on the bison burgers.
The bison burger's great.
It comes with a thick
cut of peameal bacon
on top, some garlic
aioli, and a homemade bun.
Really unique flavors.
It's delicious.
What are we making?
The peameal that goes
on our bison burger.
The wha--?
Peameal pork loin.
So we got a boneless pork chop.
And we brine it, slice
it up nice and thick,
and that's our peameal bacon.
What's peameal mean?
Ground-up yellow
peas to preserve it.
GUY FIERI: OK.
So now it's gone from
that to using cornmeal.
OK, so a simple brine.
Mustard seed, pink salt,
fresh sage, cinnamon stick,
bay leaves, kosher
salt, and peppercorns,
Quebec maple syrup, water.
So let this simmer 20 minutes.
BEN BREITLER: Strain and add
a cool brine to our pork loin.
How long is that
going to brine for?
BEN BREITLER: Two days.
- Wow.
Next up?
- Cornmeal.
So this is a Canadian thing?
I think it might
be Canadian, yeah.
We're just going
to roll it in here.
I'll let that dry in
the fridge for a day.
Right.
BEN BREITLER: Freeze it.
Because it's easier
to slice when it's cold.
Next up?
Brioche bun for
the bison burger.
This is getting ridiculous.
BEN BREITLER: So we got water,
yeast, salt, sugar, and flour.
And we're going to add
the eggs and the butter.
Let it proof overnight.
BEN BREITLER: And then
roll it out into buns.
Add egg wash and sesame
seeds and bake them off.
Let's make the burger.
BEN BREITLER: So ground
bison, salt, and pepper.
Portion six ounce.
And it's going to go on the
monster flat-top over here?
BEN BREITLER: On the
monster flat-top.
GUY FIERI: OK.
Our slice of peameal
and our brioche bun.
And then it gets topped
with cheddar, two-year-old.
Peameal goes on top.
Caramelized onion,
garlic aioli, here.
Patty on there.
Greens, house pickle.
You made the pickle.
I made the pickle.
Of course, house pickle.
Look at that.
Oh, man.
The bison is nice and rich.
The cheddar has
got a sting to it.
I love that.
And the peameal
bacon is dynamite.
Can definitely taste that brine.
Great crumb to the
bun, delicious aioli--
bro, really good burger.
Plating the bison burger.
Tender, delicious.
Really juicy.
Take a look at it.
Oh, I had it.
I had the burger.
You're preaching
to the choir, dude.
MALE DINER: It's indescribable.
Like the peameal
bacon, the cheese--
everything works
really well together.
I never heard to come
to Ottawa for the food.
This is absolutely
a destination.
And this, to me, is kind
of one of the landmarks.
Jerk chicken, table nine.
Everything you try,
it's really good.
What's your favorite
thing on the menu?
MALE DINER: I like the
banana bread French toast.
French toast
coming to your side.
The banana bread French
toast is fantastic.
It's sort of a brunch dessert.
And you get something
sweet-- some apple
compote, some maple syrup.
What are you gonna make me?
So this is the banana bread.
So we're going to
start with butter.
I'm doing this for
you, Ryder, by the way.
Ryder loves banana bread,
and he loves French toast.
Brown sugar.
We're just going to cream the
butter and the brown sugar.
Add the eggs.
Yogurt makes it not as dry.
Bananas and salt and vanilla.
Add the dry ingredients--
all-purpose flour,
baking powder, baking soda.
How many loaves of banana
bread will you make a day?
Five.
It's what I can fit in
the oven in the morning.
So we're going to
make apple compote.
I've got Granny Smith,
cinnamon, and brown sugar.
Just let that caramelize down.
But I still want the
apples to have a crunch.
And right at the
end, we're going
to add a tablespoon of butter.
GUY FIERI: Next we
make the French toast?
Yup.
We've got eggs, cream--
Keep going, buddy.
--cinnamon, nutmeg, some salt.
So it's not an overly
sweet banana bread.
No.
GUY FIERI: Good flavor, though.
BEN BREITLER: Dredge that.
Throw it on the flat-top.
Cut it on the bias.
And do our little plating, here.
Apple compote that
we made earlier,
house whipped cream, Quebec
syrup, and some powdered sugar.
You know it makes that
so good is the apple
still has crunch to it.
This has depth.
It has texture.
It has a variety of flavor.
The banana bread itself,
after it became French toast,
is 10 times better than it
was just as banana bread.
Delicious.
Whipped creaming the banana
bread French toast times two.
So good.
It's very decadent.
It's got that eat cake for
breakfast kind of feel.
Apple is a fantastic
touch on top.
Just brings the
whole thing together.
We often get it
as a third plate
to share between two people.
Ben Kamack, patio one.
I love this place because
the food's always so good.
GUY FIERI: Whatever
is driving you,
whatever makes the
machine go, is impressive.
The folks in Ottawa
are lucky to have you.
Nice job, chef.
- Thank you.
All right, Ryder.
I'll bring it home.
Quit texting me.
The phone keeps going off.
So that's it for this edition of
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives."
But don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over this country.
And I'll be looking
for you next time on--
Triple D.
All the music that you
listen here in Jax is--
actually, he plays 19
different instruments.
I can play the saxophone.
See?
I knew it.
I don't sleep.
I play the saxophone.
GUY FIERI: I know you don't.
Cowbell would have
been impressive.