Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
"The Magic Chef" will start now.
It's a culinary celebration...
Oh, look at that!
...where big time flavors
meet my big-time buddies.
I couldn't have teed that up
any better for him.
I'm rockin' Beantown
with my brother Sammy Hagar...
You're gettin' the hunch,
Sammy. You got this.
...Kansas City,
with Coach Andy Reid...
Are you hungry?
-I brought my towel.
[laughing] I'm ready.
...and one of my chef pals,
doin' it up in Boston...
Are we gonna
Lady and Tramp this thing
or should I do
this half?
...at a joint all about
what's good in the hood.
That is dynamite!
That's alright here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
& Dives."
♪♪
My brother The Red Rocker
and my business partner
in Santo Tequila,
typically we're like ships
in the night.
We both end up in a city
and we didn't even know
we were there.
But, this time, it works out.
We're here.
-Boston.
And I said, "Sammy,
you wanna go to lunch?
I know you got a couple
shows you're doin'
and I'm shootin' "Triple D."
Whaddya say?"
I say, it better be
good, Guy.
I know, I know.
-Where we goin'?
It's In A Pickle.
-Wait a minute.
We've been in a pickle
half our lives.
I know, but that's
the name of the joint.
Breakfast and lunch,
In A Pickle.
-I'm hungry.
Plating Cookies N Cream
Extreme.
These guys are known
for having innovative dishes.
They're constantly
changing the game.
S'mores
French toast tower.
Like your local best
of the best.
FIERI:
But it took a winding road
to get to this point
for chef and owner Tim Burke.
I always wanted to have
a really high-energy
Spring Break kinda bar.
Kinda like Cabo Wabo,
as you know.
Yeah! Sammy Hagar!
We in Cabo, baby!
Whoo!
I couldn't have teed that up
any better for him, right?
I'm sorry. Is that
a tattoo advertisement?
I left my job and I had
eight months
to still have enough
money for this bar.
In month nine, I said,
"I'm really in a pickle."
But not for long.
He took the name,
set up Plan B
in the City of Waltham,
just outside of Boston,
and put the craziness
into his breakfast
and lunch menu.
Toro Loco burger.
Toro Loco Burger is amazing.
Fried cheese
and onion rings on top.
It's out of this world.
FIERI:
So, what are we gonna make?
The Toro Loco burger.
So, we're gonna slice down
this pepper Jack cheese.
I do about
a 1/4-inch slice.
-That's about a half,
but okay, sure.
-I was just gonna say.
So, we're goin'
seasoned flour, egg wash.
Seasoned bread crumbs,
into the fryer.
So, next up, we're gonna do
onions and they're coated in...?
Fiery hot cheese snacks.
Blend these down.
Bam!
[ Crew laughing ]
No, no, no.
That's Emeril.
I'm callin' Emeril.
Watch this. Boom!
There you go.
So, we're gonna
add it to the AP flour,
put these in here now.
The egg wash, and then,
we're gonna put it
back into the flour.
-Doublin' down.
-And then, we're gonna fry them.
FIERI: Come on!
We're gonna make
a roasted jalapeño aioli.
It's not really an aioli,
but it sounds fancier.
-Yeah.
-Sour cream,
roasted jalapeño,
buttermilk, mayonnaise.
There's your aioli factor.
Garlic powder,
little onion powder,
dill weed,
salt, chives,
black pepper,
hot sauce.
Are we finally ready
to build the burger?
He's got sound check
comin' up.
We are ready to go.
Pepper arugula down.
Sriracha aioli.
First burger.
The jalapeño
sour cream aioli.
-That's it.
-Ah, two patties.
My goodness, gracious.
-And then, there's
fried cheese on there.
More sauce. That's great.
FIERI: Crispy onion straws.
BURKE: Yeah.
Here we go.
Oh, you're gettin'
the hunch, Sammy.
You got this!
-Oh, yeah.
You're gettin' ready.
You got a bath towel?
I'm down with the
crunchy onion rings.
Sammy's got it. The onion
rings are fantastic.
The burger's cooked perfectly.
The arugula works
as a nice little barrier.
Yep. The burger's good.
Man, I'm with you,
but there's
a lot goin' on.
My favorite of it,
really, is
that jalapeño sour cream
mock aioli.
♪♪
The cheese is great.
Well done.
The Toro Loco burger.
Spicy and fiery
and fantastic.
It's very cheesy
and flavorful.
Santa Fe omelet
ordering.
They have different
specials every week
that just go
above and beyond.
Each one, you wanna try
for its own adventure.
Tell me about the breakfast
side of things, now.
We have pumpkin bread
French toast
that'll blow your mind.
I gotta go
to sound check.
Are you scared of pumpkin
bread French toast?
Well, I'm not afraid
of anything,
except for going onstage,
weighin' about
300 extra pounds.
-[Laughing]
Thank you.
This is great.
-Thank you.
-Peace.
Pumpkin bread
French toast.
The pumpkin bread French toast
tastes just like fall.
It's topped with that
sweet cream cheese.
You add dulce de leche
caramel sauce.
It is out of control.
FIERI:
So, what are we gonna do?
We're gonna make
pumpkin bread.
-Okay.
-You want me to go?
Will it jump
into the bowl itself?
'Cause, if it will,
that's a whole new show.
"The Magic Chef"
will start now.
[ Shimmer ]
So eggs, oil,
water, pumpkin.
-Whoa. A Yahtzee.
-[Laughs]
Flour, cinnamon, nutmeg,
baking powder, baking soda,
cloves, salt, sugar.
And mix it up.
Is this your contraption?
It's just a normal
baking extender pan.
I've never seen
a normal baking --
I also don't bake.
This is us
at the Grand Canyon.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
[ Laughing ]
Let me see the magic.
What temp are we
bakin' this at?
350 degrees.
20 to 30 minutes.
-What goes on top?
-Cream cheese,
room-temperature butter,
powdered sugar, vanilla.
Mix it up.
-Okay.
So, we gotta make
the egg custard.
-Let's see it.
-Little eggs in here.
Light cream.
-What are we doin'
with the egg custard?
-Dip the slices in there.
-Oh, okay.
Vanilla, cinnamon.
Alright, let's dip it.
Dip it real good.
[ Whip cracks ]
This cooks off,
we'll put it together.
Put the sweet cream cheese
that we just made
on each one of these slices.
'Cause why wouldn't
you do that?
Powdered sugar on there.
Allspice dulce.
Little pumpkin.
Jump in. Get it.
That's more sugar
than I've had
on "Triple D,"
probably ever.
♪♪
You missed out
on this one, Hagar.
I enjoyed that more than
I enjoy a typical dessert
because you've got
a savory factor to it.
Pumpkin bread baked
that way on the sheet,
you're getting
a little bit of the crust,
but this soft,
moist center to it.
And you're getting
all the spices.
But you get the tang of the
cream cheese coming through,
so you get a little bit
of the sweet-and-sour combo.
When you're taking
that much time
to make such a simple dish
the next level,
that's why you're
doin' so well.
The pumpkin bread
French toast.
The French toast
is super cakey
and the sweet cream
is delicious.
It's really decadent.
It might be just about the
same color as your hair.
That's why I like it,
-You should.
-obviously.
Everything is
over the top.
-Quit eatin'.
-I can't.
That's the problem.
[laughing]
WOMAN:
I try to get here
as often as possible.
I know I can get
what I need here.
Congrats.
Watch out for that.
Bring six of your friends.
Come down and try it.
♪♪
Up next...I'm hittin' KC
with the chief Chief:
Coach Andy Reid...
Here's lookin'
atcha, brother.
...tacklin' the bomb butcher...
Wow.
...scoring points
with standout sandwiches.
Mmm mmm mmm mmm.
That's a real cleanup.
Cleanup on aisle Coach.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Kansas City, Missouri.
You do not roll into this town
without calling the head coach
of the Kansas City Chiefs,
Coach Reid, and say,
"Listen, buddy,
where are we gonna eat?"
We're goin'
to a butcher shop
that's also the
greatest sandwich shop
you've ever eaten at.
-The real deal?
-The real deal.
What's it called?
The Pigwich!
By the way, Gruden
gave me his permission.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-Come on, Coach.
[ Laughing ]
-Yeah, yeah.
Go, Chiefs!
Walkin' in, bánh mi.
It's just so fantastic.
Do you want
some pork chops today?
Over at the local
pig section,
you can get all of your
locally sourced meats.
Pigwich is the
restaurant portion.
You can get sandwiches,
burgers.
It's all good Kansas City
growth, man.
We're sittin' here
in farm country
and we're gettin' the
freshest farm there is.
FIERI:
And, for Alex Pope, this means
a roster of all-star meat.
Were you trained
as a butcher, or...?
I was trained
as a restaurant chef.
I started bringing in
whole animals
'cause I wanted
the best-quality products
for my restaurants.
-What's your restaurant's theme?
Everything's a sandwich,
mostly beef and pork.
If you're into pig,
get the Big Pig.
Big Pig in the window!
It's an amazing
pulled pork patty
and then, they top it
with this pork tenderloin.
Pork on top of pork
on top of pork.
So, we're gonna make
our Big Pig.
Better not be
any reference
about any present company.
-[Clears throat]
What's our first step?
The house barbecue rub.
For the pork butt
that we're getting ready
to smoke.
-Sea salt, brown sugar,
paprika, garlic powder,
ground cumin.
-Black pepper.
-Ancho chile.
A little wild card:
ground ginger.
We actually like
to let it rest overnight.
Very nice. And what
are we smokin' with?
Hickory wood.
250 for five-ish hours.
Pull it off and we put it
through our meat grinders
on the kidney dime,
which gives us big chunks.
Add ground pork.
Cooked raw,
comin' together.
Little bit more
of our barbecue rub,
minced garlic,
ground bacon trimming
from the butcher shop.
Get your patty.
-Eight ounces?
Five and a half.
-That's big.
-And boom.
Next step.
What are we into?
Pork tenderloin.
Now, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
I'm no butcher, but...
Those are bone-in chops.
Tenderloin is almost always
not an actual tenderloin,
it's a tender --
two words -- loin.
To tenderize it
a little bit more,
we do
a buttermilk brine.
Hot water from the tap.
Salt, garlic powder,
black pepper,
fresh rosemary,
ice-cold buttermilk.
-Brined for how long?
-24 hours. Up to 48 hours.
-Got it.
-Standard breading,
so, we're goin' flour,
whisked eggs,
and breadcrumbs.
Fry that all
and we're getting
a couple sauces
on this?
We're gonna do
a barbecue sauce.
We're gonna do a ranch.
-Would it be easier, Coach,
if we just asked him
the things
that he doesn't make?
'Cause I think
he makes shoelaces.
I think he's also
a cobbler.
I love cobbler.
Oh, no, you're talking
about the shoe cobbler.
I gotcha. I'm alert.
-Like you said.
-I thought we were goin'
-"Cobbler?!"
-right to dessert.
-[Laughing]
The ranch dressing is one
of your claim to fame.
Let's see it.
-So we've got eggs,
salt, sour cream.
You wanna do
the drizzle?
Canola oil.
These guys will be able
to work this out.
I'll be right back.
You know, wouldn't it be nice
to have hair like that
and then the little foofoo
on the chin?
You can pour a little
faster, now that we --
It's a little
half-hour show, guys.
Alright, so we got
fresh rosemary, scallions,
minced garlic,
celery seeds, fresh sage.
Little vinegar.
And a little bit
of brown mustard.
Fresh ranch dressing.
-Are you hungry?
I brought my towel.
I'm ready.
So, we got our
pulled pork burger.
Three cheeses: pepper Jack,
cheddar, Provolone.
I don't even know that you
have a board big enough
to list everything
that is on this.
So, we're gonna start
with ranch.
Top bun gets
our 'Nduja spread,
which is a spicy,
spreadable salami.
Our house barbecue sauce.
B&B jalapeños.
Bread & butter
pickled, B&B.
B&B. First.
Ay ay ay.
Second, third.
Grab yourself
some, guys.
Mmm hm hm hmm hm.
Here's lookin'
atcha, brother.
Don't go too far
with those fries.
[ Laughter ]
You know how
to do the hunch?
Oh, baby, I got it down.
Oh!
Look at that!
Oh, he owns this.
[ Mumbling ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Both mumbling ]
-Wow!
-I love the crisp
on the pork
and I'm lovin' the patty.
Three cheeses, man,
blend perfect.
How about the jalapeños?
Man alive.
Bread & butter jalapeños
is my new favorite thing.
The ranch dressing,
you need that cooling,
creaming effect.
My favorite part
of the whole thing,
though, is
the pulled pork patty.
My favorite part is
eating it.
-Go back ahead, Coach.
I gotta give him an A+
on hunch, though, huh?
A Big Pig for you.
This sandwich has got
so much goin' on,
between the barbecue
sauce and the ranch.
You need like five hands
to pick it up.
Gimme me the rundown. Who do
we got here from the team?
Brian Shafar,
our chief of security.
Ted Crews is our
public relations director.
My left-hand man,
Porter Ellett.
I'm telling you,
he's takin' my job, folks.
Just go ahead and do
the interview
on what they think
of the food.
Yeah. What do you think,
here, Brian?
I haven't had anything
like it before.
Pigwich is goin' up
right now-w.
Alex doesn't mess around.
He is the master
of all things meat.
Got a Porchetta.
This is the best sandwich
that we've ever had.
Alright.
Thanks, Coach.
[ Clapping ]
Throwin'
in the towel.
But not before we get
our hands on some beef!
Shortrib burger up!
The Shortrib sandwich
is one of my new favorites.
I'd say it's
a touchdown, for sure.
After these messages.
Now, where did you bring me?
I brought you here
to the central --
[ Stuttering ]
-So --
-Never gonna get my --
So, Coach Reid.
[ Laughter ]
No, come on.
You can't.
I just do the talking.
-Okay, now --
-Alright, serious time.
[ Laughter ]
[ Beep ]
♪♪
Welcome back, man.
We're here in my hometown
of KC,
where the Chiefs rule.
Alex rules a little bit greater.
-Wait, wait, wait.
Everybody knows
I'm a Raider fan.
How did he just throw
"the Chiefs rule"
right into "Triple D"?
That's the way the whole
day's been with him.
Now, while the Chiefs
might be rivals to my Raiders,
Coach Reid did bring me
to Pigwich
for a two-point conversion:
a lights-out butcher shop
also dishin' out
meat-filled sandwich bombs.
You just have so many options,
different kinds of burgers,
and the toppings
they put on them.
Shortrib burger up.
This short rib sandwich,
it's amazing.
The beef, braised in wine
overnight and shredded,
formed into the patty shape.
It's really good. [laughs]
So, we are going to make
our Shortrib burger.
Chicken stock.
We've got red wine,
onions for flavor,
garlic,
fresh rosemary,
fresh thyme.
Put a little bit
of oil in, and salt.
That's a lotta salt
because we want this
to be over-seasoned.
By the time we get
to adding the ground beef,
it's gonna be
perfectly seasoned.
Going seasoning forward.
Simmer for about
20 minutes.
This is not technically
a short rib.
It's a Texas-style
beef rib.
So, we take
our braising liquid,
pour it over the top.
Double wrap?
Plastic, then foil.
So you keep the moisture
in on top of it.
Then, we put it
in the oven
for about seven,
eight hours.
I'm gonna start
pullin' this up.
You stepping away
'cause you're worried
about the splash?
-Ah, yeah.
You won't be able to tell
when it gets on this.
Ground beef.
Rosemary.
I like this.
Copious amounts
of black pepper.
Ready to patty.
Onto the flat top.
And what are we gonna
serve this with?
Tomato jam.
So, we got tomatoes,
lemon juice, sugar.
Whole lemons.
These provide the pectin.
White vinegar,
allspice, juniper, cloves.
Little butter,
little extra flavor.
Little bit of sea salt,
blackstrap molasses,
jalapeños, fresh ginger,
black pepper, and cumin.
Cinnamon sticks
on a string.
We don't wanna
lose this
and we don't wanna
grind it up.
How long?
90 minutes to two hours.
Chill and spin.
-Time to build it.
-We wanna make it
as classic
of a burger as we can.
Start with aioli
on the bottom,
a little bit of mustard,
tomato jam.
Nicely shredded iceberg.
Short rib
goes right on.
Okay, boom.
Let's get that thing cut up.
What do you think?
-I second that.
-Coach?
Alright, baby.
As you can see,
Coach is enjoying
the Shortrib
patty sandwich
that he's inhaled
half of it already.
It's just
a healthy bite.
Wow. Whatever this
balance that you're
putting together,
it's really working
because I am getting
the all-American burger,
but I'm getting
this flavor punch.
This 55-item tomato jam
all sings through.
Do we need to do it again?
I mean, just take a bite,
just for the camera's sake.
♪♪
Mmm mmm mmm mmm.
That's a real cleanup.
Cleanup on aisle Coach.
Here's your
Shortrib Burger.
It's nice and crispy
on the outside,
so, when you have
that bite,
you get the really
unctuous flavor.
The tomato jam is basically
a better version of ketchup.
It's fresh-tasting.
Buffalo tenderloin
up in the window!
I would eat here
every single day,
[laughing] if I could.
It's phenomenal.
When I called Coach
and I said,
"Where do you wanna go?"
He picked it. Boom!
Well done, brother. Congrats.
-Thanks, man.
Keep it up.
Coach, thank you, man.
-Hey, man.
If there's some
YouTube channel
of you doin' food
shows, we're gonna talk.
Comin' up...a real
local joint in Boston...
It doesn't get any better
than that, right?
...where I'm bringin' in
another wingman..
This is like an Abbott
and Costello thing goin' on.
...for more
supersize sandwiches.
For you guys,
I'm gonna make you
somethin' special.
-What a nice guy.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Boston and you
roll into a town like this,
you call your chef buddies
and say, "Hey, where do I go?"
So, I've got Ming Tsai
and I got Michael Schlow
and I call my buddy
Kenny Oringer.
Now, Kenny, you've got
restaurants here.
You got Little Donkey.
You've got Toro.
What else?
-Coppa and Uni.
Real underachiever,
isn't he?
Alright, so where
in Boston are we?
This is the North End.
This is the Little Italy
of Boston.
And we're here to check out
a joint where this dude,
he's been runnin' up
and down these streets forever.
He's had his
grandfather here,
his uncle, his cousins.
-BOTH: everybody.
-You say the food's legit?
-Absolutely.
Awesome. This is Pauli's.
We're gonna need
a lot more clam chowder.
It's gonna be
busy today.
It's just good New England
food. It's fresh.
Lobster roll.
If I have people
from out of town,
this is where
I'm bringin' them.
Cinco de Mayo burger!
Pauli's probably one of the
nicest guys in the North End.
I mean, he's been here forever.
Well, 45 years ago, my uncle,
my grandfather,
opened up, across the street,
a little store.
My Uncle Joe was like,
"I remember when I used
to change your diapers
on a bag of oregano."
-Well, that's a sell
point, right?
-Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
And then, my mom comes around
and she was like,
"I wanna do something."
What is this, a mini-series
it's turned into?
Fast-forward then
to Paul Barker,
headin' back to the neighborhood
with his own namesake spot.
Is it an Italian deli?
Is it a local cool spot?
Woof!
It's actually a really --
Was that a woof
that you just gave me?
We say, "Woof!"
-I just gave you a woof.
It's a tough answer
because he has pretty much
a sandwich for every
single person.
Fat Felix.
The Fat Felix is what I get
when I really wanna
treat myself. [laughs]
You get it loaded
with marinated steak.
The cheese is
all melted on top
with a bunch
of grilled vegetables.
Melts in your mouth.
Just unbelievable.
What are we gettin' into?
Steak marinade
for the Fat Felix
sandwich.
Start with ketchup,
butter.
Brown sugar.
Worcestershire.
Molasses, apple cider
vinegar, Dijon.
That'll light ya up.
-Sazón.
-Black pepper.
-And...
We're holding off
on that, though.
On the cayenne?
We're holding off?
So, I bring this
to a boil
and I put
the cayenne in.
20 minutes.
-Why?
I don't know.
It's just the way
I've always done it.
-Hmm.
Now, we're gonna make
the steak tips.
Flap meat,
like a sirloin butt.
-Do you know steak tips?
-Flap meat?
-Yeah.
-Oh, yeah.
-No, I know flap meat.
-Do you know steak tips?
-I love steak tips.
But do you know it comes
from flap meat?
-Yes.
-This is like
an Abbott and Costello
thing going on.
[ Laughing ]
So, this is cooled down.
I love the Dijon
in that.
But the cayenne,
the last 20 minutes
really makes
a difference, right?
You can taste the nuance.
-[Laughter]
-You guys are killin' me.
Doesn't miss
an opportunity.
Marinade for 24 hours?
-Yeah.
The last thing we're
gonna do is cheese sauce.
So we're gonna start
with a little roux.
Butter, flour.
-There we go.
Whole milk, cheddar.
Little
processed cheese.
And then, we got American,
Provolone, Swiss.
-Little hot sauce.
-More than a little hot sauce.
Salt and pepper.
Let this cook down.
Last thing we gotta do
is throw the tips on?
Yep. We got peppers,
onions, and mushrooms
that've been seasoned in olive
oil, salt, and pepper.
Ooh, look at this guy.
He's like Benihana here.
[ Clapping ]
-Look at this guy.
-I hate when people
steal my one-liners.
American cheese. Now,
we're ready for the fill.
Some French fries,
cheese sauce, bacon bits.
'Cause it might need
a little more flavor.
Here's our Fat Felix.
How did it get the name
the Fat Felix?
Felix invented it.
-Felix that works here?
Yeah.
[ Funk plays ]
I love the texture
of the steak tip.
It's not like
a cheesesteak where
it's kind of like
flat steak.
It chews like you're
eating a real steak.
[faux-crying] I love
to see him take over.
That's exactly
what it is.
You're getting more chew,
more bite, more texture,
coming out
of this flap meat.
And then, you have
that fantastic marinade
that plays into it.
The roll, it's like a great
roll down in New Orleans.
-Yep.
-At first, I was like,
"You know, what's up
with this guy?
Why isn't he toasting that?"
-I was the same thing.
It absorbs everything
kinda like, you know,
French dippy almost,
you know?
French dippy al--
[ Laughter ]
Hey, listen if you just
put on 60 pounds,
bleach the hair, you could
cover the Thursday shift.
[ Laughter ]
It's delicious.
Fat Felix pickup!
It's the perfect mix
of savory, salty.
With the great
steak tips
and the cheese
and the bacon,
it's got everything you'd
ever want in a meal.
We got a Lobsta mac & cheese.
You can get a great dish
of pasta or pizza,
no matter where you go
on the North End.
Pauli's is different.
He was one of the first
sandwich shops.
U.S.S. Lobstitution,
pickup!
U.S.S. Lobstitution.
This is 10x your
typical lobster roll.
I never can eat it
on my own,
but I've tried more times
than I care to admit.
Where's this lobster
coming from?
-Okay.
-And don't say the sea.
-[Laughing]
-It's all locally sourced
-Okay.
-New England lobster.
So we got claw meat.
-Poached off.
And we have
knuckle meat.
We like to start
with some mayo.
Lemon juice.
So, that's
the lobster stock
the lobster came in.
I like that!
That's all that we're
putting in for seasoning?
The bread's gonna do
all the work
and the lobster meat's
gonna do all the talking.
This is about the most
straightforward
that I've seen, besides
eating it on the boat.
This is what we normally
do. You know what?
For you guys,
I'm gonna make you
somethin' special.
Thanks, Pauli.
What a nice guy.
Whoa! Holy moly.
-Biggest lobster roll in Boston.
What gave you this idea?
This is insane.
We like to do crazy things
here at Pauli's.
Split it on the top.
Hit it with some
of that butter.
Alright, on the grill.
-Put it on the grill.
How many ounces of lobster
are goin' in this thing?
It's almost
2 pounds of meat.
That is insane.
Are we gonna
Lady and Tramp this thing
or should I do this half?
[Laughing]
-No, we're not doing that.
♪♪
That is pure lobster.
Man, is this
thing good.
It is not hiding
in anything.
You get the butteriness
and the sweetness
of the lobster
shining through.
That lobster stock
adds a lotta moisture.
There's a little bit
of mayonnaise in there,
just for a little touch
of some extra fat.
Normally, you get
a lobster roll
and it's kind of heavy.
This is so light!
That's legit and probably
the most honest lobster roll
I've ever tried.
♪♪
[muffled]
That is dynamite!
I have the
U.S.S. Lobstitution.
Fantastic sandwich.
There's not a lot of fluff.
Tastes like it just came
out of the water.
Never had anything like it.
Here's clam chowder.
Pauli's is awesome.
I live on the stuff.
I'm actually like
half Pauli's right now.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Body by Pauli.
That's nice.
Pauli, you're
a gentleman, man.
It doesn't get any better
than that, right?
-Oh.
-Good job, Chef.
-Thank you.
So, was this a great
road trip, or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country!
I'll be lookin' for you
next time,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
& Dives."
I gotta go
to this sound check.
I gotta teach Guy
a thing or two.
He's got a lot to learn.
He can pick this baby up
at the gig tonight.
[ Engine starts ]
[ Laughing
delightedly ]