You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That one joint you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doing?"
You know what? I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
It's all right out of the ocean.
You catch your own octopus.
Yeah.
In Honolulu, Hawaii.
The best.
poke's popping up
all over the place.
Watch out baby.
And it's no guts...
[ Yells ]
...all glory.
Mmm! I could sit here and eat
this by the bucket full.
Plus...
Do they really scream fish on?
Two sea fearing souls.
Yeah. They scream all kinds
of different things.
Spreading their love of
fresh fish all over San Diego.
Dude, you got a PhD
at the college by the sea.
And someone
we've never met on
"Triple D" is helping out
his Hawaiian community.
This was a big deal.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
Alright, Hunter.
It was 2012 the first time
we went to one of
this guy's restaurants.
Since then he's become
a really good friend of ours.
We come over to islands
all the time
and we hang out with them,
but I've got to be
honest with you.
He's opened another location,
four food trucks
and we haven't been
to any of them.
This is Fresh Catch.
We saw it on "Triple D"
and that's why we're here.
It's the freshest
poke on the island.
MAN He brings in the fish
fresh every morning
and they cut it right back here.
FIERI:
He's talking about chef,
owner, and my chain brother,
Reno Henriques.
Yeah. Yeah. This is real.
This is real, my man.
Run DMC called. They said that
they left their bling here.
[ Laughs ]
What's up, brother.
How are you doing?
Bro, you're busy busy.
HENRIQUES: Yeah,
you can't get in, buddy.
Ever since your show aired,
life changing, brother.
Yeah.
Two Ahi Katsus.
FIERI: But what hasn't changed
is the wide variety of
poke he's got going on here.
HENRIQUES:
We make shrimp poke, salmon
poke, imitation crab poke,
Ahi Limu poke.
Okay.
[ Imitates
"Jaws" theme ]
Holy tuna.
This is a bigeye tuna.
Look at this thing.
Can I give you one hi-ya.
[ Yells ]
So, we take the knife
right down the center.
Look at that.
There you go.
That's your basic Ahi filet.
We're going to cut it up
and make some poke with it.
What is poke translate?
Poke is small cuts.
Small cuts?
Yep. Do you remember that poke?
The first one we made,
that Ahi Limu?
Yep.
So the Ahi with the seaweed
and your favorite kukui nut.
Kukui nut after you roast it,
it kind of looks like this.
You just put a rag over it.
Going to smash it up.
That's your kukui nut.
You don't eat too much of it.
It's kind of like
a Hawaiian laxative.
[ Record scratches ]
Now I tell you.
[ Laughs ]
Alright, so we got
the crazy nut.
Alright,
we got our crazy nut.
So now we got our
Ahi cubes in a bowl.
We're going to to season it
with some Hawaiian sea salt.
Then we got our kukui nut.
Hawaiian chili flakes.
We've got our Hawaiian chili
pepper water,
sesame oil, a couple of mixes.
Green onion.
We got some white onion.
Our limu or seaweed.
Give it a couple good
mixes again and there we go.
We've got our basic
Ahi Limu right there.
♪♪
I could sit here and eat this
by the bucket full.
It's tender, it's fresh.
It's so balanced
and so delicate.
So flavorful.
That's legit.
[ Laughing ] Yeah.
[ Normal voice ] It was so
popular that we're actually
putting one of our
new sauces to it.
It's a
Hawaiian Asian sauce.
So we got some fresh
yellowfin tuna.
Okay.
I know you love
this Hawaiian style poke,
but I'm taking up
another level for you, buddy.
Whose head did you put on?
What's that skinny body?
That's actually my head
on your body.
Is that what it is?
Good. I thought so.
For that Asian blend, basically
it's like an oyster kimchi,
with a bit sweet chill.
Oh, my God, man.
It's excellent, man.
Something different.
Breakfast, lunch,
and dinner.
It's killer.
It's a little salty.
It has a little bit of a crunch
with the Limu and the onion.
And then you have
that soft fish.
The fish is fresh.
It's silky, soft,
melts in the mouth.
FIERI:
And there's a reason for that.
Everything is fresh from Hawaii.
Got to have real deal.
The ocean is in our backyard.
Most people ain't got
that opportunity.
We go diving.
Catch our own octopus.
Fishing boat --
[ Whistles ]
You catch your own octopus?
Yes. It'll kind of be
in the hole
hiding with his little hand
over there.
How is that?
You got to get one of these.
Like, like that?
Yeah, there you go.
That's probably about a four
to five pounder right there.
It's that new hairdo
I was looking for.
Squid locks.
[ Laughter ]
Going to make one
of our most popular pokes.
It's a spicy smoked tako.
Tako, T-A-K-O.
It's octopus.
In Hawaii, we call it he'e.
The next thing we want to do
is put the octopus in the bowl.
Put the Hawaiian salt
on top to tenderize it
and take off the slime.
Okay, my man, so now we're just
going to cut it off.
That.
Yeah, so now we're just going to
string one going right through.
Where are we going
with this rod of fun?
Right into my smoker.
This is the Diabolo 5,000.
Come here. We have got
some aluminum siding.
I think he cut the hole
in here with a hatchet.
You've got this crappy
little smoker
out of a office.
What was it?
File cabinet. File cabinet.
Filing cabinet.
This is old school style.
As he explains it to me,
he walks around with the octopus
and keeps smacking me
in the legs with it like that.
Let's smoke some octopus.
How long are we
going to smoke this?
Four hours. Don't ask me
what temperature it is.
When the paint
starts to peel off
a little bit,
it's just about ready.
Alright.
HENRIQUES: Since the show,
we've been tripling
the production of our tako.
so that file cabinet
have to get upgraded.
Let's go.
Alright, now we're going to make
our sauce for our small tako.
And always we use a lot
of mayonnaise on that.
No. Wasabi.
And then we have
our kimchi base.
Mm!
These are my home grown
chill peppers from at my house.
They're hot?
They're hot, man. Whisk them up.
Alright, we got
our cut octopus.
Dump it in the bowl.
We've got our spicy sauce here.
A couple of good mixes.
Now people come in
and buy this to go?
Eat it here?
We make poke bowls.
Two scoops rice
and like a hoagie tray.
A hoagie tray.
So this is like hoagie poke?
Yeah, hoagie poke.
Then you do a little
hokey to the right,
a little hokey to the --
A little hokey poke.
Garnish it with a little bit
of green onions and then
tobiko fish eggs.
There you go, my man.
Good to go. Yeah, there you go.
You got great texture.
The octopus is tender.
Good heat in the mayonnaise.
That's outstanding.
FIERI:
And coming up, the memories
keep flooding back.
And it gives me goosebumps.
And wait till you see
what's coming out of that
filing-cabinet smoker
these days.
This is delicious, bro.
Smoke meat plate.
Thank you, my brother.
♪♪
FIERI: I'm on Oahu
checking in on good buddy
and poke phenom Reno Henriques.
What's up, brother?
How are you doing?
I first met him at his original
joint Cone O Hei back in 2012.
[ Yells ]
But apparently, that wasn't
the first time
our paths had crossed.
Mmm!
[ Laughs ]
Go back on the day
we were shooting a place
called Nico's Pier 38.
We go with him over
to see the fish auction.
And we're there.
We're at the fish auction
and I'm hanging out
and there is this character
with the chicken headband
and the whole thing.
This is before we ever knew him.
This is before he ever knew.
HENRIQUES:
I was there, in the background,
and then two years later.
Dude,
it gives me goosebumps.
And he's still shopping local
to make over
30 different kinds of poke.
How many times today are you
refilling these of poke?
Anywhere from 10
to 15 times a day.
10 to 15 times a day.
Wow.
So you take a tray,
grab the raw ingredients,
rebuild the tray,
put it back out there.
Yes, sir.
You don't have just big tubs
of it sitting in the back?
No. All fresh to order.
♪♪
FIERI:
But these days, he's not just
serving up seafood.
What is this, Reno?
This is a smoked pork
called Hawaiian bacon.
So we got a basic
teriyaki marinade,
shoyu, brown sugar,
some garlic, minced ginger,
Hawaiian chili pepper.
Then we're going to
slice our pork up
and then we're going to marinate
overnight for about 24 hours.
And then we put it
in our file cabinet.
If you did not get rid of
the filing cabinet by now --
No, it's beautiful now.
It's all fixed up.
Going to let it smoke
for four to five hours.
The pork is smoked.
It's all sliced up.
I'm going to drop it
in a deep fryer for 30 seconds.
Then we're going to
put some butter garlic,
Maui sweet onions.
And then we're going to add
our smoked pork to it,
the Hawaiian bacon.
Going to hit it
with some oyster sauce
and then we're going to put on
our black magic teriyaki sauce.
And there you guys go, bro.
This is delicious, bro.
That pork is good, huh?
HUNTER: So good.
MAN:
It's full of flavor.
It's just the right amount
of sweetness
versus a little bit
of sauciness.
The texture of it is not
too chewy, not too soft.
It's just right.
Thank you, my brother.
FIERI: I'm proud of you, man.
You have done such a great job.
I can't tell you the amount
of people that beg that you come
and open on stateside.
Why don't we get one?
Then you have another reason
to come visit us.
I'm getting kind of popular
nowadays.
You know, I'm taking
pictures every day.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
Once and awhile I'll sign
a autograph here or there.
Watch out, baby.
We should make sure
that we thank Mr. Reno
for the delicious poke.
[ Laughs ]
The best.
Alright, Hunter,
clean out the deli case.
Let's go.
[ Laughter ]
Seriously Reno, I'm not kidding.
Fresh Catch on the mainland
would kill it.
And I'm sure we can
find a nice space
probably, you know,
in Santa Rosa right by my house.
Now next up in San Diego.
You have no idea what's coming.
Another joint that's
reeling them in.
You're 100% in your fish.
And dishing them out.
Two Track Tacos.
Money, bro. Money.
FIERI: You can't throw
a rock in San Diego
without hitting
a fresh seafood joint.
I mean, they're everywhere.
But two brothers who learned
the fish biz before
they can even drive decided
to throw their hat in the ring.
And boy did it pay off.
SERVER: Cali sandwich.
This is Blue Water Seafood
Market and Grill.
WOMAN:
It's the greatest quality
and best prepared seafood
in San Diego.
This is the real McCoy.
After "Triple D,"
things just took off for them.
FIERI: We're talking about
owners and brothers,
Matt and Judd Braun, who opened
this place back in 2004.
All we do is fish.
Seriously? No burgers?
No nothing.
No steaks, no hot dogs.
That's because they were
catching them way
before they were cooking them.
JUDD: I've been doing fishing
my whole life.
You're out on fishing boats?
Yeah, working on sport boats.
Started out as a deckhand and
then I ended up being the cook?
And do they really scream
fish on?
Yeah, I scream all kinds
of different things.
[ Laughs ] You're breaking
the fish down 100%.
You're 100% in your fish.
I love it.
It's the hard way to do it,
but it's guaranteed quality
every time, you know.
It's the best way to do it.
Now, how much does this
monster weight?
It's about a 40 pound fish.
I was cutting a large
Alaskan halibut, which is not
a very difficult fish to cut.
Give me the rundown,
brother.
Come straight down
right along that spine,
but right back up the tail.
You're running right on top
of those bones.
You've got perfectly halibut
filet loin.
And then your skin it
and then cut it down.
That's it.
I was so amped up
and so eager to do it.
Then I filleted that thing
in two seconds.
You've just given like
a documentary
on how to cut a fish.
I've learned more than
I learned in school.
Killed it.
Right on.
So now you cut it and then
it goes back to your brother.
It goes back to my brother --
And then he cooks it.
Then that's what
someone's going to eat.
That's exactly right.
It's either going to be a salad,
a taco, or a sandwich.
Or a plate.
Now what are
my marinade choices?
Chipotle, teriyaki,
lemon and butter,
and lemon garlic butter.
Let's do that piece
with teriyaki.
Roll it in breadcrumbs.
Teriyaki.
Ah, you can smell that ginger
right off the bat.
Top of the salad.
Fresh avocado.
Nice. What a nice salad. Mmm.
So much flavor from that fish.
Teriyaki's on point.
Money, bro. Money.
FIERI:
And those greens are host
to a brand new dish flavor.
Wasabi seed, sesame crusted
seared Ahi salad.
With avocado.
Definitely one of our best
selling salads.
MATT: First hand-cut a killer
piece of Ahi tuna.
Next we're going
to put on our crust.
Wasabi, sesame seeds,
coarse sea salt.
coarse, black pepper.
Once it's crusted,
drop it on the grill,
put a very light sear on it,
maybe 30 to 45 seconds.
Flip it and drop it and then
it's ready for our salad.
And it goes really good
with vinaigrette dressing.
Honey, Dijon mustard,
red wine vinegar,
soybean oil, and a little
black pepper at the end.
Bed of greens, red onions,
diced tomato, carrots, capers,
cucumbers, a lemon wedge.
Side of dressing and avocado.
And lastly,
our tuna goes right on top.
Two Ahi salads, table five.
It was cocked perfectly.
The seasoning was great.
The vinaigrette
doesn't overpower it.
It really compliments the fish.
MAN: Really nice
seasoned crust on it.
It wasn't too peppery
or too spicy.
Really, really enjoyed it.
Okay, before I fill up
on this, I got to try a taco
because you come to San Diego,
Mexican food prevails.
So if I was going to go
for a fish
from the case for taco,
what would you recommend?
Let's do a sea bass taco.
Sea bass.
Get your Chipotle marinade.
How fast will this go?
About two minutes?
About two minutes.
And where do you get
the tortillas from?
El Indio.
I knew that. Two years ago,
I shoot that tortilla monster
machine over there in the I
Love Lucy conveyor belt thing
that I had to go through.
Here, watch the clip.
Wah-aah.
[ Laughs ]
See how sad that was?
Tortilla goes on.
Let the cheese melt.
Mmm.
That's great, man.
That fish is so nice
and light and flaky.
Chipotle's got
some nice heat to it.
The kicker is the melted
cheese on the tortilla.
That's one of my favorite
fish tacos I've ever had.
Culinarian over the there.
College by the sea.
Dude,
let me tell you something.
You got a PhD at the college
by the sea, Dr. Fish Taco.
[ Beeps ]
FIERI:
And now the doctor's operating
on a whole new version.
Using shrimp called the
Track Taco.
First thing we're going to do is
make our Maui onion mango slaw.
We're going to mix together
cabbage, shredded carrots,
sweet Maui onions, jalapeños
and fresh mango.
Next, our sauce,
which is olive oil, honey,
fresh lime juice, coarse sea
salt, paprika, and cumin.
We're going to mix that up
and it's ready to go for a taco.
We use a Pacific wild shrimp.
Throw that right on the grill.
Dress it with our Chipotle
and butter marinade.
Next we're going to warm up
a fresh corn tortilla.
Melt some cheese.
Once the shrimp is ready,
drop it on the tortilla, and
drop our Maui onion mango slaw,
avocado,
fresh tomatillo sauce,
and a little bit
of queso fresco.
Track Taco ordered up.
Two Track Tacos.
MAN:
A lot of good vegetables,
a nice flavor
they have in their slaw.
It makes the sweetness
with the Chipotle
on the shrimp kind of combine
like a burst of flavor
when you're eating it.
Really good.
JUDD: Nobody can describe
the busy-ness
that comes with doing
a "Triple D" episode.
You have no idea
what's coming.
Literally tripled
our business overnight.
Kind of scary.
Yeah, man.
It allowed us to upgrade
our kitchen
and now we have
our new store here.
Congratulations, man.
You put your blood,
sweat and tears into doing it.
Nice to meet you, brother.
Absolutely. Good stuff, guys.
"Triple D Nation"
is always welcome back 100%.
I am so glad to see that these
dudes are still crushing it.
And you heard him.
It's all thanks to you.
Now coming up in Kona,
he's acting like a pirate
and cooking like one.
An island joint new
to the nation,
[ Shings! ]
going global to help the locals.
It's just fun.
FIERI:
I don't know about you,
but whenever I come
to the Hawaiian islands,
I always think
about pirate ships.
You know, what was it like back
in the day
between the islands
and all the trades?
Well, on the big island
about 20 minutes
south of the Kona airport,
there's a dude that must've
been thinking the same thing
because he's acting like
a pirate and cooking like one.
This is Privateer's Cove.
♪♪
We have Mammoth Filet
going to the rules table.
The food is outstanding.
It's out of this world.
I've never had alligator
and bison and elk and camel,
but I've had
all those things here.
FIERI:
And the man taking his diners
out of their culinary
comfort zones,
that would be Nick Traxler,
who says he's collected
these recipes
while traveling
around the globe.
We are doing craftsman food
from all over the world
that we put our heart
and soul into.
FIERI: That includes this
tongue twister,
the whiskey Thai chili
pulled pork belly lumpia
We're going to start off
by taking a pork belly
and just roasting it
in the oven at 350
for three and a half hours.
Pull off the skin.
After that, we're just
going to shred it
and then we're going to add
in the onions, carrots,
and then we got green onions.
And we're going to mix
that all up.
Throw in our chicken base,
some sweet chili
and our whiskey.
And we mix it again.
This roasts for another
30 minutes to an hour.
We're going to roll the pork
belly up in the lumpia wrappers
and we're going to
seal them with egg wash.
And we'll drop them in the fryer
for three or four minutes.
And that's that.
All they get is a sauce on top.
The Thai chili,
homemade Irish cream sauce.
How many people get to make
their own Irish cream?
I mean, it's just fun.
Sweetened, condensed milk,
heavy cream,
dark Belgian chocolate, vanilla,
and then we have ground
instant coffee.
And then we're going
to add the whiskey in.
Throw that into the coffee press
to press out any grounds
and any fine spots.
Once it's completely finished,
we're going to it
with the sweet chili sauce
and then it's ready to go
for our lumpia.
♪♪
It's nice and crispy
and the pork is full of flavor.
It is like a Filipino egg roll.
It's sweet
and it's different flavors
from different
parts of the world.
Privateer's Cove donates 100%
of its profits
to run a community center
run by us.
This was a big deal.
He's going to make great things
happen for this community.
TRAXLER: We have a children's
center, a veteran center,
and we do free movies.
WOMAN: It serves many different
community projects.
It's very Kona,
it's very relaxed,
and it's delicious food.
FIERI: Like his version
of seafood cannelloni.
We've spiced it up using
a Hawaiian chili pepper Alfredo.
Hawaiian chilies, garlic,
table salt
and some white wine vinegar.
And that will sit
for six months to a year.
We mix one tablespoon with one
quart of cream. That's our base.
Then we're going to use
another cup of cream
just to thin that out more.
Otherwise you're going
to burn people.
We heat up the cream
with a little bit of Parmesan.
Now we're going to make
our seafood cannelloni.
We're going to start out
with little bit of oil,
butter, garlic,
and a little teaspoon
of our Hawaiian chili sauce.
Now we're going to add
in the shrimp and scallops.
Throw it into the bowl.
The next thing
we've got is the crab
and then from there, mozzarella,
Parmesan, ricotta cheese.
Some mascarpone cheese.
And that's going
to be a filling.
And then we're going to throw it
all in a piping bag
and we're going to pipe it out
on these pasta sheets.
We'll roll up the pasta sheets,
top them
with a little bit of mozzarella
and throw in the oven
for about eight minutes at 350.
I put the chili Alfredo
on the plate
and then we're going to put
the cannelloni
right on top off the pan,
garnish it with green onions,
and then send it out.
SERVER:
Seafood cannelloni right there.
The cheese mixes it all together
with Alfredo sauce on top
and the spice
from the Hawaiian chili.
Just excellent.
MAN:
The sauce is creamy, has garlic.
It's a lot of flavor.
It's pasta like I've never had,
but I love the flavors.
I want to give you something new
in a way
that you don't normally see it,
but we want to do it in a way
that we can help
our community as well.
Dishing out and giving back,
now that's the way to do it.
Just like how our other spots
are still doing it up right.
Like my pal Reno,
pounding out poke
at Fresh Catch all over Oahu.
And the Braun brothers,
serving straight off the hook
at Blue Water in San Diego.
Plus there's plenty more tales
to tell next time on
"Triple D Nation."
Rubbish man?
Rubbish?
Rubbish man.
Pick up rubbish.
Trash.
Yeah. Trash man.
You call it rubbish, though?
Yeah, rubbish.
Sounds a lot sexier
than trash man.
[ Laughs ]