Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
This trip...
I love it.
We're crossing the country...
I'll have all that to go.
...for a wild ride
through Flavortown.
I mean, it is, like, goosebump
time, it's really spot on.
We've got a comfort cooking
brew house in Santa Fe...
So now we're getting chef-y.
...a bagel emporium in Boston...
It's of the best we've ever
had on the show.
...and a funky spot in Reno...
Out of bounds.
...going big time
with the big game.
Bro, please tell me
this is on the menu forever.
That's all right here
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
I love this food revolution
that's going on right now,
I mean, people are getting
so connected to their food.
And I love coming back
to cities that we shot
"Triple D" in years ago,
and seeing what's going on.
So I'm here in Reno, Nevada,
and I got to tell you the food
revolution is alive and well.
This is
the Washoe Public House.
Sticky Thai chicken wings,
five minutes.
Washoe Public House
is one of a kind.
Two Irish Nachos.
This is, like, my happy place.
-[ Laughs ]
-I'll have what she's having.
It's out of the norm of Reno,
and Reno needs out of the norm.
Your wild boar schnitzel.
There was a need for something
that I wanted to,
which was from scratch,
seasonal, super high quality.
FIERI: And when it comes to
putting together
his wild menu, chef and owner,
Brett Moseley's
definitely got game.
Brett's a huge outdoorsman,
big game is huge in
the northern Nevada community.
Double elk chops going down.
Brett cooks a mean elk chop,
better than any steak
I've ever had.
Just outstanding. Pretty much
you're licking the plate.
FIERI:
What are we gonna make?
Double elk chop.
Dark red meat,
really great for
a medium rare steak.
Excellent.
The first thing we're gonna make
our luxardo cherry demi-glace.
Okay.
Luxardo cherries are
the original maraschino cherry,
and they're, like,
really dark red.
We're gonna start
with veal bones
that have been roasted.
Carrots, onion, celery.
Water going in this.
-Then we'll reduce it overnight.
-Got it.
Then we add red wine,
let that reduce by half.
Add our Luxardo cherries.
So we're gonna sear
this double elk chop here
with kosher salt
and fresh ground black pepper.
Throw it into the oven.
While that's working, we'll work
on the potatoes and the squash?
Yep. Roasted russet potatoes,
salt, pepper.
And we're gonna sauté
our pattypan squash.
Right.
A little bit of salt and pepper.
Starting get some color on it.
Garlic, shallots.
I think
our elk chop's almost done.
Gorgeous.
Hit it with some butter,
so we can baste it.
Look at that technique,
bringing all those flavors
off the bottom of the pan.
-Our fine herbs.
-Fine herbs.
-He's just getting all fancy.
Parsley, tarragon,
chervil, chives.
A little bit of lemon juice
to finish. Add a little butter.
-More fine herb.
-Lemon zest.
Got a lot going on just
for the side dish, boss.
Potatoes and we hit it
with the fine herb, lemon zest,
and a little lemon juice.
And we're ready to plate up.
Potatoes down first,
squash, elk chop,
a little bit
of that demi-glace.
Garnish with pea shoots.
Beautiful.
Nice medium rare,
great crust on the outside.
That's fantastic. Look at that.
It's rich, tons of flavor.
Super tender,
dynamite compliment
with this cherry demi.
The pan-fried potato,
you get this nice crunch,
and then a creamy
velvety potato inside.
There's good texture
in that squash.
Being that you're a hunter,
you know how to treat it.
I mean it is, like, goosebump
time, it's really spot on.
Excellent.
And your double elk chop.
The tenderness of it is amazing.
With the luxardo cherry demi,
it's top-notch.
Almost exotic, because it's not
something you find everywhere.
Spinach cappelleti
with ricotta.
Reno, we've changed a lot.
High quality food
really came in.
Brett's restaurants centered in
the heart of the community here.
Everything on the menu
is a winning item.
I got four orders of
wild boar schnitzel all day.
Wild boar schnitzel
is a really great dish.
He does a pickled
mushroom on it.
With the spatzle,
it's a gorgeous German dish.
-What's on the menu?
-Wild boar schnitzel --
-Okay.
-...with rice spatzle.
Schnitzel and spatzle goes
together like Bogie and Bacall.
-I don't know who that is.
-What?
-We have to talk.
-Rye flour.
-Rye not?
Yeah. AP flour, some eggs,
a little bit of salt, pepper.
We got an imperial brown ale,
they make it right down
the street.
Blanch it in boiling water,
by forcing it through
a perf pan.
You got to go quick.
Chef, great technique.
That is the quickest
I've ever seen it done.
-Blanch it in the cold water.
-Stop the cooking process.
Mm, I liked that little
rye note in there.
Something different.
I'll have all that to go.
What are we into now?
It's a garnish for the dish,
which is pickled mushrooms.
So I have rice wine vinegar,
water, soy sauce,
brown sugar, fish sauce.
-Wow.
And then we've got
three kinds of mushrooms here.
Brown albas, white albas,
king trumpets.
Pour that hot brine,
and let it rest overnight.
Now we're on to...
The schnitzel with the seasoned
flour breading.
AP flour, cornstarch, salt,
pepper, cumin, smoked paprika,
chili powder, fennel seed,
mustard powder.
Anything that you haven't
put in there?
Old Bay, garlic powder,
onion powder and some clove.
Wing of bat, and eye of newt.
And you're using
wild boar tenderloin.
Why not?
Butterfly it a little bit.
Plastic wrap on top.
Pound it out,
then we're gonna bread it.
A little bit of milk,
panko breading,
that we put dried thyme into.
Fry, 350.
-Okay.
-We're gonna make the spatzle.
Really hot pan, a little bit
of oil, salt, and pepper.
I'll let that crisp up
on one side.
Lemon zest and fine herb.
-Throw this arugula in here.
-Nice touch.
Fresh lemon juice.
-Beautiful.
-We've got our schnitzel.
Mushrooms on top.
Pork belly gravy.
Gosh.
Garnish with some
of those pea shoots.
I can't even cut into it.
It's too pretty.
♪♪
Wow.
The schnitzel's super tender,
and really rich with flavor
with that wild boar.
The gravy is just a kiss.
And the acid of the mushrooms,
cuts right through
and separates the dish
into so many different levels.
Without question,
one of the best schnitzel
spatzle combos I've had.
Bro, please tell me
this is on the menu forever.
Out of bounds.
Here's your wild boar schnitzel.
You know, I've traveled
the world including Germany,
and there's nothing like this.
Spatzle, it's really good.
This is the international
tasting stars,
my friend Lily and her family.
What do you think of this
wild boar schnitzel and spatzle?
Really good.
It's kind of, like, tangy?
And the pasta
that tastes really good.
Your pork belly egg rolls.
Washoe Public House is
a top 10 place in Reno.
My favorite place
to come and dine.
Bro, I'm a fan. Well done.
Thanks, man.
FIERI: Coming up, a Santa Fe
brew pub serving comfort grub...
Beautiful, huh?
...like a wicked
chicken biscuit...
I give you props.
...and a fresh take
on classic bowl.
That's my kind of
clam chowder right there.
♪♪
I'm here in beautiful Santa Fe,
New Mexico
in the midtown area.
About, I don't know, five
minutes away from Meow Wolf,
you know where they have
that really cool art experience?
It's interactive.
Well, I'm here to check out
a brewery
where two buddies are making
farm ales and wild beers.
And if they're going
to all that trouble
to brew those specialties,
you got to know that the menu
is gonna be off the hook.
This is Rowley Farmhouse Ales.
Cheers.
This is the neighborhood pub
with the above average pub fare.
Cream sauce for the green
chili cheese fries.
It's off the beaten path,
but the food is really great.
-You come for the food?
-I come for the food.
You're double-fisting it
right now,
and you come for the food?
-That one's coffee.
FIERI: And the one,
two keg kitchen punch
was all part of the plan
when John Rowley
and Jeffrey Kaplan
partnered up on this place.
I wanted to do like a gastro pub
with good beer.
And he wanted a farmhouse
brewery with good food.
What kind of food you guys do?
We do like farm to table
dishes we all grew up with,
but just a little upscale.
Chicken biscuit with fries
in the window.
The chicken
and biscuits sandwich
is one of my go
to comfort foods.
That biscuit of course,
really sells it.
Really, really tasty.
We're gonna do chicken
and biscuits?
Yeah. We're just gonna
start off with the brine.
Hot water, garlic powder,
kosher salt, some sugar.
Throw it in ice
to cool that down,
so we are not scorching
the chicken.
Chicken breast, chicken thigh.
We do an airliner
that we cut the wing off of.
So the airliner
was to make the food
a little bit fancier
on the airline.
They would leave
the wing connected to it.
But I also heard, because
it's still got the wings,
so it flies.
I haven't heard that one.
I'll go with that, also.
-So you just trim off this.
-We trim off that.
Save that for wings later.
Yep. We just want to
make it a little more flat.
We're gonna let
this brine overnight.
So now we're getting chef-y.
We're gonna go sous-vide?
Correct.
We're going to bag it up,
put it in our Cryovac machine.
What temp are you running?
165, and we let this go
for about an hour.
Par-cook it a bit,
so when you're breading it
and frying it,
you're gonna be able to
achieve that really nice crisp.
And not have to wait for it
to cook all the way through.
Exactly. It stays nice,
and juicy and tender
all the time.
Dredge it in rice flour,
and fry it at order.
-We've got to make the biscuit.
-Yep.
So we add our flour in, salt,
baking soda, baking powder.
Mix the dry a little bit.
We're gonna add
our cold butter in.
-Local goat cheddar.
-Goat cheddar, really?
Yeah. Green onion, as well.
And last but not least,
the buttermilk.
As soon as this kind of
all sticks together, it's done.
Dump this out on here.
And then we're gonna do
a little fold on it,
and we're gonna do
that a couple times to make sure
we got some nice layers.
We've got
our little custom maker
that's a little bit bigger.
That's a big biscuit.
It's a big sandwich.
I'm a big guy.
-And what temp?
-350 for about 18 minutes.
All right, Jeff, let's see it.
-Toasted our house-made biscuit.
-Okay.
And we're gonna put
a little horseradish crema.
Our chicken breast that
we just took out of the fryer.
House-made pickles.
Real thin batter on that chicken
from the rice flour,
but it's super crunchy.
Yeah.
And then our onion rings
from the rice flour as well.
I love it.
Nice tender biscuit.
Mm, great chicken.
This is tender, great flavor.
You're definitely getting
a little bit of the brine.
It's a light crisp fry,
and the brine of the pickle,
and the horseradish sauce
is dynamite.
I give you props.
Chicken biscuit sandwich.
The chicken is fantastic.
It's moist, it's fresh.
The biscuit is just phenomenal.
I think that's one
of my favorites.
I think that goes with beer.
The beer is great.
John Rowley's the master brewer.
Makes wonderful barrel-aged
and farmhouse ales.
He and Jeffrey are some of
the biggest beer nerds I know.
You get that nice
vanilla flavor in there.
The beer shows so much
character,
the food reinforces it.
New England clam chowder, up.
The New England clam chowder
is the freshest
you can get in Santa Fe,
New Mexico.
The presentation's
totally different.
With the clam
still in the shells.
FIERI: It's an a la minute
clam chowder.
We build the dish
one at a time.
We get live Manila clams in.
We're gonna clean them,
and we're gonna try to
simulate the tide pool,
because that's
what clams like.
Beautiful, huh?
We let these chill out in water
like this
for about half an hour,
and then we'll strain them out.
Keep them alive,
keep them happy.
We never want to serve the ones
that are already dead.
Then we're just gonna cover
this with a nice wet towel,
pour some ice on this.
-Next steps?
We're gonna cut up
a little leek,
and then we do the corn.
Ah, that's a cool trick.
I've never seen that before.
When you're doing volumes
of corn and you don't want to --
-Yeah, yeah.
-...chase it all around.
Sweet. All right,
now we're ready to cook.
Olive oil, bacon.
Get that a little crispy.
The leeks, shallots,
and our garlic.
Then we're gonna add
in our clams.
That's my kind of clam chowder
right there.
Heat things up a little bit,
add some white wine.
Cover this to steam it.
So he's keeping all the flavor
of all those clams
in that little pan.
Make sure they're all open,
make sure they all look good.
And if they weren't,
we'd pick them out?
Pitch them out, yeah.
Heavy cream, potatoes, too,
which are par-cooked
all the way through.
Bring that back to a boil.
We're gonna add
a little salt and pepper.
Throw our corn in here.
Got a little parsley
and some tarragon.
Tarragon is a nice kick there.
Kind of looking for that
right thickness right now.
Just gonna
plate it up here.
Nice little mountain of clams
in the center.
A little fresh lemon zest,
and oyster crackers.
♪♪
Mm, what I just got there,
was a little kiss
with the tarragon
and a little bit
of the lemon zest.
Big piece of sweet corn.
Bites of bacon, creamy potato.
Broth is nice and light,
and not heavy.
Just the right amount
of white wine.
Just a touch of the cream,
and really delicious
fresh clams.
Well done.
-New England clam chowder.
-All right.
The clams
are completely tender.
They've got a great flavor.
The tarragon just gives it
a little licorice lift.
I think it's
a fantastic dish.
-Cheers.
-Great neighborhood spot.
They put a lot of passion
into everything they do here.
Watch out for this guy,
it'll hurt your waistline.
Nice job.
Up next, the bomb bagels
in Cambridge, Massachusetts...
The only thing that
I don't like
is that one-quarter
of it's already gone.
...out of the ordinary...
Every move you make.
...and stacked to the max.
You're a dangerous woman,
I'm not kidding you.
♪♪
So I'm here in
the Cambridge-Somerville area
right outside of Boston,
to check out a joint
where this chef was gonna
be a school teacher.
Well, she kind of change gears
and decided to open a restaurant
offering up
one of my favorite things.
It's something that takes
so much time, so much energy,
and it's really
a labor of love.
It's bagels.
This is Bagelsaurus.
♪♪
Eggspanola, olive.
Bagelsaurus is by far
the best bagel place in Boston.
Just really unique
creative flavors.
Grabbing two sea salt,
and an onion.
Immediately when I walk
in the door,
my mouth starts watering,
because I can't wait
to dig right in.
FIERI: And Mary Ting Hyatt is
the one ruling over this
bagel-making kingdom.
How did you become
the bagel queen?
People weren't really making
great bagels in this area.
And you come from the lineage
of great bagels?
I have always loved bagels.
How many bagels do you
make in a week?
6,000 in a week.
There's got to be
little elves here
if you're making 6,000 bagels
out of this tiny little joint.
We need three jumbos.
Mary came up with these bagels,
and she really
puts her heart and soul
into every single sandwich.
She's ruined BLTs for me.
I can no longer
have them on toast.
They have to have them
on a Bagelsaurus bagel.
There's a whole slew of bacon.
There's oven roasted tomatoes,
which are sweet.
And there's a spicy pepper
cream cheese that is delicious.
FIERI: What's the deal?
We're going to make a BLT
with this onion bagel.
-Let's see it.
-Water, our sourdough starter.
That's a day ago
that you built that?
-Yep.
-It's proofed.
Malt syrup, flour, table salt.
I'm gonna let this go
for a little bit.
Instant yeast,
roasted onions.
The onions by themselves
are awesome.
Poppy seeds.
This'll mix for
about nine minutes.
-Proof the dough.
-Yes.
During those couple of hours,
we're going to do
a series of folds
that simulates hand mixing.
Then how does it go
from that stage
into being made into a bagel?
Then we like to cool it
for a little bit
in the fridge, and then --
Are you sticking with me
on this?
I mean, we've only
been here for an hour
and we're only
in the mixing part.
-Bagel dough's coming out.
-Whoa.
That's one huge bagel,
that's too big.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna let them rest.
This is like six days
in making one bagel.
There are different ways
you can shape a bagel.
You can do like a snake,
wrap it around --
How was, hang on,
what was that part again?
Like a snake.
Oh, that looked like
a dance move to me.
Yeah.
Or you can do the hula.
-So through there --
-With a little flair, yeah.
See that with a little knee
bend I threw in there?
Oh, yes.
They're going to proof
for a while,
and then rest overnight
in the fridge.
These are gonna go
for one more day?
-That's right.
-Oh, my gosh.
We do a quick boil,
30 to 40 seconds.
Next step?
This is the final step,
so we're just gonna
put them in the oven,
believe it or not.
-No, that's impossible.
-Yes.
We have to do something to them.
How long is this gonna bake?
About 20 minutes, 450.
So bagels are out of the oven,
and what are you
gonna make me?
-Spicy pepper cream cheese.
-Okay.
We have pickled jalapeños
that we made.
So house pickled jalapeños.
We have roasted poblanos,
and then blast those up.
Red chili flake, salt.
Blend that together
with our cream cheese.
So we also make our
oven-roasted tomatoes in-house.
We have plum tomatoes,
tossed with chopped garlic,
salt, sugar, pepper, thyme,
extra virgin olive oil.
And they go in 250-degree
oven for four hours.
-Okay, chef.
-Our onion bagel. Toast it up.
Spicy pepper cream cheese,
and our oven roasted tomatoes,
red leaf lettuce, bacon on top.
Love it.
♪♪
The only thing that I don't like
about this bagel
is that one-quarter
of it's already gone.
[ Laughs ]
As a bagel, it's of the best
we've ever had on the show.
Light, tender,
great chew, bacon's great.
But these oven-roasted
plum tomatoes,
the acid of that cut
with the fat,
and the spiciness
of the jalapeños and poblanos
in the cream cheese,
you're a dangerous woman,
I'm not kidding you.
I appreciate that, Guy.
BLT with spicy cream cheese
on an onion bagel.
You get some sweetness
from the tomato
and some smokiness
from the crisp bacon.
The spicy cream cheese
has a lot of, like, heat to it.
My sinuses open up. So good.
If these two look familiar,
it's because you tuned into
"Triple D"
like seven years ago.
Rachel and Charles
from Cutty's.
I find out today
when I'm visiting Bagelsaurus,
that our chef was working
for you back in the day.
She was working for us
when we filmed
"Triple D" and she started
making bagels at Cutty's.
She started with a few dozen
bagels, and then --
-Grew, and grew.
-Grew.
And then she had to move out.
I would say that Bagelsaurus
kind of started
the bagel movement in Boston.
It's become its own landmark
for the area.
So here's the deal,
we're hanging right outside
of Boston at Bagelsaurus.
And when we come back
we're meeting the bagel's
unholy cousin.
Hot smoked on a bialey.
Bialeys are so good.
They're just like a big old
dough that's not boiled.
And ingredients baked
into the center
is what makes it so good.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Guy, I'm gonna need those.
-Sorry.
-Thank you.
Welcome back, "Triple D"
hanging out at Bagelsaurus
in the Cambridge-Somerville
area.
You opened up a bagel shop
that is serving over
6,000 bagels a week,
13 different types of bagels.
And didn't you go and create
dishes with these bagels,
so you're not just a bagel shop,
you're bagel restaurant?
-Did I get it right?
-You got it, yeah.
Whew.
They have sweet bagels,
and savory bagels,
and they're always
a little on unique.
Like the bialeys
are really good.
A bialey is like a thinner
version of a bagel
and it's a little bit
more delicate.
Hot smoked on a bialey.
A hot smoked is bunch of
hot smoked salmon,
and then pickled cabbage, dill,
with cream cheese.
It is so delicious.
We're going to make something
called a bialy --
Okay.
...which is another traditional
Jewish bread product.
The difference is,
we don't boil these.
Okay.
And we can use the same dough
that we use for our bagels,
so they've already done
all the resting.
I'm not gonna put you
through that again.
So, we're gonna
close the holes.
Okay.
And we're gonna fill it with
onions and poppy seeds again.
You love your onion
and poppy seed, don't you?
-I know.
-Maldon salt.
A little maldon on top,
just to be fancy.
Spray them with a little water
just to give them a little bit
of steam in the oven.
-It just gets a bit of a mist.
-A mist.
All these get done
in the oven, what temp?
Around 15 minutes, 450.
Now what are we into?
Now, we're making
our pickled cabbage
for the hot smoked sandwich.
-All right, let's see it.
White vinegar, water, sugar,
salt, mustard seed.
And a lot of garlic.
Bring this to a boil,
pour it over.
That's gonna sit over night,
and then we're ready
to build our sandwich.
-Let's see it.
-Onion, poppy bialey.
Plain cream cheese
on both sides.
Sliced red onion on the bottom.
Hot smoked salmon.
Our pickled cabbage here,
and a lot of dill.
That is a big dill.
-That's all she wrote.
-There we go.
♪♪
It's mindful, it's creative.
You have that huge acid
hit from that cabbage,
compounded with the smokiness
of that salmon,
that the refreshing side
of that dill coming through
just brightens the palette.
I mean, it's just
every move you make.
-Thank you.
-You are one wicked woman.
Here's your hot smoked
on a onion, poppy bialey.
You get the saltiness
of the salmon,
but then the pickled cabbage,
and the dill really
cut through that.
This bialey's unique because
it has that nice thin size,
so I get that chewiness
and that crispness
at the same time.
Just like an absolute
insane sandwich.
Chicken salad, olive bagel.
I can't really eat other bagels
after having Mary's bagels.
I walk out of my way
to come here for it.
It's so good.
How are we making bagels
and you're not my size?
Nice job.
Thanks, Guy.
Wicked.
So was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
Jump right in, rock star.
She'll be taking over the show.
You'll be catching
her new episodes next
Thursday, goodbye.
I don't let everybody do this,
I just let the rock stars
do this.