You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That one joint you checked out
in that one city,
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
Mmm!
It's Triple D's take on turkey
and all the trimmings.
That's awesome.
The New Orleans joint do
a turkey day their way.
So worth five bucks.
With a lot to talk about
all year round.
Tell me guys what do you think
of what you're having.
[ All talking at once ]
Plus an Albuquerque eatery...
That's what she gave me.
...trickin' out
the turkey sandwich.
I couldn't shovel that
in my face fast enough, could I?
And in Boston...
That's a nice, giddy up.
...a diner where every day
could be a holiday...
Thanksgiving in September,
February.
...but turkey's not the only
bird flying off the line.
This is legit
fried chicken.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Alright, Hunter,
are you hungry?
I'm always hungry.
Excellent.
So we're here in Boston and I'm
bringing you to a triple D-O-G.
I mean this joint
is one of the first places
we ever shot in Boston.
-Here we go.
-This guy is a legend.
He's competed on "Triple G"
a bunch of times.
Congratulations buddy.
This is Jay Hajj's
awesome joint.
This is called
Mike's City Diner.
So I love "Triple D."
I knew Mike's was going to be
on there so I had
to come and check it out.
Jay has everything that you
would expect of a normal diner
but he puts his own twist on it.
-Turkey dinner.
MAN: You into this place is
known for the turkey,
the stuffing, the cranberry, the
mashed potatoes, it's delicious.
And you don't have to wait
till Thanksgiving to eat
FIERI: Not something you'd
expect from Lebanese-born chef
and owner Jay Hajj.
What sized bird is that.
Look at that thing.
You know all the images people
are having right now
of Thanksgiving and their mom?
How many years ago was this?
That was 2007.
You were I think without
question one of the first
and definitely
one of the most memorable
still doing the big turkey
the same way?
Yes, Thanksgiving dinner.
So what do you think the key
is to cooking a good turkey.
Is it dressing like a pilgrim,
is that part of it?
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
We're not going
to season this.
No seasoning.
Unless you want to
eat the skin.
I find that it doesn't give
any extra flavors for me.
But if you say so,
I will agree with you.
[ Laughter ]
And I'm still doing it
the same way.
I'm not seasoning my turkey.
Now the stuffing.
FIERI: Celery, carrots.
Just dump them in
Dump them right in.
We're not gonna sauté
them or anything?
Oh, no, no, no.
That's for fancy place.
-White onion?
-White onion.
white pepper, cumin, seasoned
salt and the Pulitzer season.
Whisk.
Well, we let it simmer
for about five, 5-10 minutes.
Put it right in here.
Wow.
Now I'm going to
smash-amattic.
Now we've got to bake this.
We want a nice crust on it.
Everything you do is got
a little magic behind it.
Wow.
Turkey super tender.
That's stuffing is money.
Could still taste the texture of
the vegetables.
That's really good.
-Thanksgiving in July.
Yeah. Thanksgiving in September,
February.
About time you want it.
We're known for Turkey.
Turkey hash, turkey sandwiches.
Those are our pilgrim
sandwiches, you guys.
We're gonna make a
pilgrim sandwich.
Okay. Okay, so cranberries.
Put stuffing in it.
That's a nice, giddy up.
Holy enchilada. How much
you gonna give 'em?
It's best to eat it
with a fork and knife.
I got the gravy.
Stuffing.
That's awesome.
Thanks.
That stands up there with
the best turkey sandwiches
I've ever had.
Mmm!
Since we filmed
the last "Triple D,"
we still sell a lot of Turkey,
but now we're known for other
things like the fried chicken.
Alright. This is
the refried kimchi chicken.
Refried kimchi chicken.
Where's the kimchi?
-It's in the batter.
-Yeah.
-Give me the rundown.
HAJJ: You get the kimchi, we put
them in a food processor,
locally sourced kimchi,
better than I could make it,
mix it with buttermilk
add the brined chicken
soak overnight.
Before we fry it,
we've got to season the flour.
A little paprika, white pepper,
celery seed, and salt.
And then we put some of the
kimchi in the flour and mix it.
We'll cook it about 75 percent
and then it stays overnight
And fry it again
for three minutes.
We got some Belgian waffle mix
that we make in-house.
Here we go.
Powdered sugar.
Now we put
the chicken right on it.
then we serve it up with
sriracha lots of hot syrup.
Okay, ready, Hunter?
-You gonna feed me?
-Mmm! Mmm.
This is
the fried chicken sandwich.
[ Mouthful, talking ]
What were those words?
We're not even finished with
this and he sent more out here.
You know we have the waffle,
the sandwich, any way you want.
Okay,
I'll tell you what,
that's good fried chicken.
-Thank you, sir.
-This with the hot syrup...
-Yeah.
That's dynamite.
I mean, it's moist on the
inside, it's crispy,
but that sriracha syrup
is awesome.
The kimchi fried chicken,
unbelievable.
The waffles are to die for.
Alright.
Gonna try this one.
HAJJ: Same chicken,
the kimchi fried chicken.
Coleslaw and some chipotle
mayonnaise on it.
This is dynamite.
With the slaw.
-This is legit fried chicken.
-Thank you.
It's a nice blend of a little
bit of heat a little sweet
and then the kimchi,
just takes it to the next level.
So what happened Jay?
You've changed a little bit.
-Yes.
-You're not the guy
that was wearing
the gigantic white chef coat.
Now you have these big muscles
you're a boxer now.
Well, yes. I just had a fight
my first flight.
Did your first fight.
How'd you do?
I did well. I knocked the guy
out on the first round.
Knocked the guy
out in first round,
you can't get enough
of that on tape.
[ Bell dings ]
-And when we come back...
-You're kind of like
a big celebrity around here now.
-Made me into a big shot.
FIERI:
The ring isn't the only place
he's not pulling punches.
-He's got the right ratio?
-Well, that's why it's so good.
FIERI:
He's hoisting up the belt with
his breakfast bird match-up.
It's almost like duck bacon.
This is money. Hash.
When I think of Boston
I think of the Tea Party,
I think of the Sox, of course.
And now a place called
Mike's City Diner.
FIERI: That was 2007, back in
those early "Triple D" days
and not much has changed since.
FIERI: The restaurant
still looks the same.
Was it what I told you
it was gonna be?
Yeah.
But Hunter and I aren't the only
family members taking notice.
So this is my cousin Rooker,
his wife Shannon,
and these two were the two girls
that I was holding.
Say, "Yum, yum."
Say, "Eat him up."
-Big bite.
-Eat it up.
Eat 'em up! Mom who eats more,
mommy or daddy?
-Daddy.
-Mommy? Daddy does?
You remember eating
this sandwich when you
were little girls?
Do you remember making
the piggy noises?
GIRLS: No.
Do you want me to play it back
for you, so everybody can see?
-Oink, oink.
Come on, do the little piggy.
[ Imitates pig snorting ]
ROOKER: Oink.
[ Laughter ]
So what are we gonna make?
The corned beef hash.
We got potatoes...
Potatoes.
...and onions.
Onions.
You got corned beef...
Corned beef.
...and we got mashed potatoes.
Mashed potatoes.
Is that the right ratio?
That's like a four to one.
Well that's why it's so good.
Alright. Let's go.
What we do is
we grind the corned beef.
Oh, I get to play with this.
You put the onions last.
This will clean it right out.
Okay so
now cut the potatoes?
And we cut them
with that little can,
that little gadget
that I made.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
you made this?
Yes.
You know we should do
is get a piece of string.
We make a telephone out it.
[ Laughter ]
We're going to go in here,
the mashed potatoes.
Alright.
We bake it and then we cool it.
It goes in the flat top
after it cools.
I love it man.
♪♪
I love the crunch.
I always could have a little
crunch on the outside.
This is money hash. There is
so much corned beef in that.
I almost feel like I'm having
a corned beef sandwich
without bread.
That's some good hash, brother.
HAJJ:
Now you know we have
other hashes,
the duck confit hash.
Okay.
So give me the rundown.
We have onions and peppers
in here as well?
Pepper bacon, carrots,
onion, celery.
Now a little bit of
Mike's bone-in ham.
Garlic powder, onion powder,
smoked paprika, and salt.
Now we're going to
put our duck confit in.
Let it cook down a little bit.
We're going to put the potatoes
last when people order it.
That's when we put it
in the griddle
and we let it crisp up about
a minute, minute and a half.
♪♪
The duck is super tender.
It's almost like duck bacon.
It's got
a little sweetness to it,
got a little saltiness to it,
it's got a richness to it
from the duck.
And there's carrot in there
for sure.
A nice little sear and a little
crunch from the flat top.
That's a mature respectable
legit hash.
That is awesome.
The bite into the duck
on your teeth
is just kind of satisfying, the
quality of the meat is so good.
WOMAN:
It has a great sear on it
and has a little more flavor
than you'd expect from a normal
hash because of the duck.
What we love to see
is that you take what you have.
You didn't change that.
The diner still looks the same,
the place is still packed,
the line's still
out the door.
You just continued
to improve upon it.
I wrote a book since then
a cookbook memoir.
And you wrote the forward to it.
Bestseller.
You write?
I had Ryder do it.
You're kind of like a big
celebrity around here now.
You made me a big shot.
Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
I love it.
Hey look I just shined
the light on you,
you became the big shot
all on your own, my friend.
Now coming up
in the Big Easy.
-Hey.
A surprising seafood stuffing,
that's so good...
This is like food
Mardi Gras right here.
...you'll just want
a bigger spoon.
How ya like them apples?
Back in 2010 I was
on a very specific road trip.
We're rolling out for jerky
and stuffin' "Triple D" style.
And this point in New Orleans
had just what I was looking for.
-Turkey dinner
with oyster dressing.
-They're still trotting out
the turkey and the trimmings,
but you gotta check out
what else
they're stuffing these days.
This is Sammy's
Food Service & Deli.
♪♪
I saw Sammy's on "Triple D"
with the turkey and stuffing.
I immediately knew this was
going to be my one-stop,
go-to place for Thanksgiving.
MAN: Roast beef sandwich,
cheeseburgers, shrimp,
you name it, it's here.
That's thanks to
Sammy and Gina Schlegel
who've been cooking
and catering
French Quarter classics
since 1991.
When I got the call from
"Diners Drive-Ins & Dives,"
I said,
"Are you kidding me?!"
-This is his favorite show.
-Absolutely.
Good man.
I thought it was gonna go
through the roof.
Let's talk about
Thanksgiving.
Well, if we do
a traditional turkey
we stuff with the oyster
dressing a good combination.
Turkey stock here
just runs like fine wine.
Okay. Well, give me the rundown.
-All right.
First thing we're going to do
is get our bed set up
for Turkey to lie on.
Celery, garlic,
coarsely chopped onions.
We'll put our bird on here.
Paint him up, put a little
garlic butter oil.
I want to take
our poultry seasoning here.
Get them all well seasoned.
We're gonna put our
chicken stock put it in there.
That's gonna make
some great gravy
on the bottom of this,
which is turkey.
Absolutely.
Okay. Now stuffing time.
Got a little milk there.
Give it a nice little creamy
taste here.
Sauté some celery,
red bell peppers,
onions,
green bell pepper.
I'm gonna need a spoon.
How ya like them apples?
Please don't
ask for a mixer.
[ Laughter ]
Take our oysters, put them in
this little choppin' machina.
Break them up a little bit.
That's not something
you see every day.
We just want to show how
New Orleans does Thanksgiving.
Red pepper flakes,
black pepper,
some Cajun seasoning,
bay leaves,
béchamel in here now.
Is that you're five bucks
on the floor over there?
Oh, man my lucky day.
Look at this!
-So worth five bucks.
-Stuffing a bird.
Tucked his legs in
give him a little truss.
Bird's gonna go in 350.
Hour and a half?
Correct.
Put it on a plate here.
This is what you've been
and waiting for, right here.
-Right out of the bird.
-A little topping of the gravy.
Mmm.
Dude, that's super tasty.
The turkey
is ridiculously tender.
The stuffing has great texture
to it, big flavor.
You can really taste
the oysters. Mmm.
The Thanksgiving dinner
has exploded since the show.
I mean it's just unreal
the amount
that it has impacted
our catering business.
This is like food
Mardi Gras right here.
There you go.
FIERI: And oyster dressing
isn't the only seafood
stuffing you'll find.
They've also got one loaded
with shrimp and crab.
First ingredient
are mushrooms,
green onions, celery,
and bell peppers.
Now we're going to
sauté it in butter.
We have granulated garlic.
chicken base.
Paprika, lemon juice,
Cajun seasoning.
So now we can add
in our pureed shrimp.
And our crab meat.
Now we're gonna add in
the pepper cheese
because it's going
to tighten it up
and give it
a really good flavor.
FIERI:
And that's going right inside
a bayou staple -- catfish.
Okay, so this is some
smoked paprika,
Chesapeake Bay Seasoning.
We're going to cut our catfish
in the center here
so we can stuff it
with the seafood dressing.
Now this will go in 350
for 20 minutes.
Okay, now we're going to make
the shrimp and crab cream sauce
that goes on top of it.
Heavy whipping cream, garlic,
dill, paprika,
Cajun seasoning,
chicken base, Parmesan cheese.
Then we put in the cooked shrimp
and crab meat to top it off.
Seafood stuffed catfish.
It tasty, light, creamy.
It's just perfectly seasoned.
MAN:
The stuffing is not too heavy
and the cream sauce
is just to die for.
And when you put
a couple extra shrimp in it.
It's the best.
Tell me, guys, what do you think
of what you're having?
[ All talking at once ]
♪♪
Being on the national stage,
it changed a lot of things.
As soon as it aired,
things were much busier.
It just leapfrogged us
into a better day.
This is really the heart
and soul what "Triple D" is.
It's about all-American people
living the all-American dream
and making it happen.
I love regional takes
on traditional tastes
and sounds like the rest
of the nation does too.
Now, coming up in Albuquerque.
Another joint throwing
a curve ball at the classics.
This is like
"Triple D" gone wild.
And this time I didn't even
see it coming.
Mmm. That'll
rock your lunch.
FIERI: I was in Albuquerque
back in 2013,
When I met a chef not only
slow roasting
all her meats...
-Coming at you, babe.
...she was also roasting up
a New Mexico staple.
Wow.
Nowadays she's still
choppin' those chilies
and adding 'em to
just about everything,
including her take
on traditional turkey.
This is Bocadillos Slow Roasted.
-Cuban named Ruben for Isaac.
Best sandwich shop
in Albuquerque,
best sandwich shop
I've ever been to actually.
Guy he brought Bocadillos out
to the world.
And owner Marie Yniguez has
fully embraced the limelight.
After "Triple D,"
Everything went nuts.
Guy just blew us
out of the water.
FIERI: I was just
returning the favor.
Awesome.
I mean this is like
"Triple D" gone wild.
I've never seen a
chili-roasting stand.
He didn't know what
a chili roaster is. [ Laughs ]
-Crazy.
-I know.
You know, come to Albuquerque
will show you what's up.
My mouth is already
starting to water.
It smells so killer.
Look at that.
Isn't that beautiful?
And we're going to
cook with this?
Yes, sir.
We're gonna make
the green chili apple chutney.
This is typical chili
peeling in New Mexico.
-But you wearing gloves?
-Oh, yeah.
Because...?
Because you don't know
if you're gonna touch your face
or anything else later.
What would anything else be?
[ Laughs ] Who knows.
I've heard some stories so.
Yeah.
And this
chilly apple chutney
is going to
go on the turkey?
Yes. We actually did the TNA.
The TNA?
TNA.
What does TNA stand for?
Turkey and avocado.
Crushed peppers, garlic,
salt, pepper.
Little bit of brown sugar.
Dry rub goes on?
Dry rub goes on.
That right there is our
house-made honey mustard.
Just go ahead and toss it on.
Good to go.
Pretty. Wrap it up in foil,
stick it in the oven
for 12 hours at 250.
Alright. Roasted turkey.
It just falls apart.
That honey mustard
rocks the house.
Pretty sick, huh?
green chili apple chutney.
Let it soak into
the turkey.
Got the Munster cheese
is going.
As in Herman?
As in, there you go.
Your very own TNA.
That's what she gave me.
Okay?
That's a sandwich.
No, that's a dinner
for six.
The sweet and the heat,
with the roasted turkey
and the mustard,
it's delicious.
And a little burn of the chili
in the back.
It's just the love.
It is the love.
FIERI: Now those chilies
are part of this new number.
We're making
the Big Dipper.
This is our version of the
French Dip, New Mexico style.
First step is you gonna get
a good piece of chuck roast.
Makes my mouth water.
You shred it and we let a cool.
Next, we're gonna make au jus
New Mexico style.
We're just going to sauté
a little bit of onions.
Going to add the green chili,
beef stock,
and let it go for about
two hours.
Through our meat down,
add the green chili,
caramelized onions.
We'll top it off with
pepper jack cheese.
Green chili au jus.
Big Dipper for Amy.
Your whole entire face just gets
covered in the juicy meat.
Everything in the au jus
just brings all the flavors
of the Big Dipper out.
-Being from New Mexico,
I do love how it has
green chili.
Salty and savory,
melts into your mouth.
We are from the good
old Duke city,
Albuquerque, New Mexico.
It is called "the Duke City"?
The Duke City.
Like John Wayne the Duke.
No like the Duke
that found Albuquerque.
Really?
Yes, sir.
There was a duke that found
Albuquerque?
Duke City Ruben is
what I also have, Guy.
Start get your jaws going.
Put our pickling spice right
on top of that corned beef.
Get it rubbed in
a little bit.
Put a little bit salt, pepper,
a little bit of garlic.
That's all she wrote?
Mm-hmm.
Put it in 12 hours.
In the oven 12 hours?
Now we make the sandwich.
Yes, sir.
Corned beef,
a little bit of our
homemade sauerkraut,
set that right on top.
put a couple of pieces
of Swiss.
♪♪
It's tender not too salty.
I couldn't shovel that in
my face fast enough, could I?
That'll rock your lunch.
FIERI: These days
the Ruben's teaming up
with another player to create
the ultimate sandwich showdown,
A Cuban Named Ruben.
We start with fresh pork butt
bone-in.
Salt, pepper, garlic, cumin.
Red chili powder.
My new little mix.
We hit it with
a little bit of brown sugar.
Put in the oven 250 degrees
for 12 hours.
This is our
slow roasted pork, man.
Just falls apart.
We're gonna keep
the natural juices from the pork
because we're gonna use
this juice as our sauce.
We call it cubano sauce.
So it's kind of
like a sweet chili sauce.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna let it come up to a boil.
Thicken this with a little bit
of cornstarch
a little bit of slurry.
We're going to warm up our pork.
We're gonna warm up
our corned beef,
sauerkraut right there,
sweet chili sauce on the pork.
Raw red onions on there
throw the bacon.
We're gonna put our asadero,
Muenster,
and a little bit more
of the cubano sauce.
We're gonna
grab our corned beef,
stick it right on top
of that pork.
♪♪
The Cuban Named Ruben.
MAN:
The best of both worlds.
You get that
slow roasted corned beef
from the Duke City,
and then you get that
sweet from the onions
and the pickles.
It's amazing.
♪♪
I'mma tell you something.
You're priceless, girl.
And it comes out
in your food.
The bomb.
Thank you.
Yeah, there's plenty
of personality poured into
all these "Triple D" dishes.
Like Marie's green chili chutney
topped turkey in Albuquerque.
Sammy's seafood-infused
stuffing in New Orleans.
And the Thanksgiving-all-year
plate
Jay's got going in Boston.
And there's even more places
to park the Camaro.
Next time
on "Triple D Nation."
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
I don't need a napkin,
just hose me down later.
[ Laughter ]