♪♪
So Hunter and I are here
in Juneau, Alaska.
HUNTER:
Wow, this is beautiful.
It is,
and just like you guys,
we show up in a new town,
and we're looking
for a place to eat.
We know
we got great seafood.
We know we got
a tourist destination.
It's also the capital.
And it's also the capital.
GUY: Which means it's filled
with all kinds of local gems...
That's crazy town
right there.
...like reindeer pie
on a wood-fired pizza wagon...
Well, there you go
then.
...Asian-Mexican fusion
served in a cellar...
This is like
a multicultural playground.
...and a food trailer
warming up the winters
with their hearty,
heaping helpings.
I would order it
and order it again.
This is
a special edition --
Hunter and Guy
"Triple D" in Juneau, Alaska.
Hunter, are you hungry?
Oh, absolutely.
He's always hungry.
♪♪
Alright, Hunter.
Here at our first stop
in Juneau, Alaska,
what do you want
to eat?
The question is, are we
going for Korean,
or are we going
for Mexican?
I don't know.
I mean, I could go
for some bulgogi,
but tacos do sound pretty nice.
How about a joint that's
doing a funky fusion
bringing them
both together?
Oh, I like that.
That's what
I'm talking about.
This is V's Cellar Door.
Okay. Korean short ribs,
bowl of pozole.
Let's go!
When you first hear
"Mexican-Korean fusion,"
you're like,
"Oh, like, I don't know,"
and then my mind was blown.
Tinga Fusion Burrito.
WOMAN:
Everything here is really fresh.
The flavors go really well
together.
It's always enjoyable.
GUY: The good times come
courtesy
of Chef Venietia Santana...
Order up.
...a Sicilian-Irish chef
who ended up tackling
Asian-Mexican flavor.
My ex-husband is
from Mexico City,
and we would go there,
and the food was amazing.
Married now?
No, I'm engaged.
Fantastic.
Congratulations.
But you're married?
Yes, I am.
Five minutes with me
and my cooking,
you'll be like,
"Wife who?"
What did she just say?
Can you cut, please?
WOMAN #2: It's just a really
good feeling being around V.
She's got so much energy,
so much attitude,
and it really shines through
each dish that she makes.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
WOMAN #3: It would have
to be the fusion nachos.
Korean chicken fusion nachos.
WOMAN #4: There's melted cheddar
cheese and Korean chicken,
and there's their fusion sauce.
Everything in a nacho
that you could want
but never knew you wanted.
Let's get into it, V.
What are we making?
Korean chicken that's
gonna go on top
of our Korean
chicken fusion nachos.
Chop up
our chicken thighs.
Next up, marinate.
Ginger, green onions,
pear, sesame seeds,
garlic, soy sauce...
Sesame oil.
Good job, Dad.
Thank you.
...brown sugar,
sweet onion.
And gochujang, my favorite
Korean ketchup.
How long is this chicken
gonna marinate?
15 to 20 minutes.
Next up, V,
what do we got?
Our fusion sauce.
Soy and brown sugar,
gochujang.
Sesame oil,
rice-wine vinegar.
Hunter.
♪♪
Oh, yeah.
Have that on cold cereal.
I would take a cup of that
with a straw.
Next up,
what are we doing?
Salsa.
Gonna make salsa.
Oh.
Good catch.
Come on.
White onions,
Korean pepper flakes,
gochujang,
Roma tomatoes,
tomatillos, orange juice,
sweet chili sauce.
Do me a favor.
In the back of the Camaro,
go and get the pipe wrench
and undo the kitchen sink
because that's the only thing
we haven't put in here.
Green onions, garlic,
fresh ginger,
cilantro, lime juice...
Holy cow.
...sesame oil.
This is the salsa.
We're still just
on nachos, folks.
The fusion nachos.
Thanks for tuning in
to the mini series.
Let's build these nachos.
We're gonna sauté
the chicken, little bit of salt
and pepper, chips,
beans and then cheese.
Do it again.
What happens when the rest
of the people
are ordering food,
and we're spending all day
making magic
nacho mountain?
Well, I'm a woman,
so I can multitask.
Got it.
Ooh.
We're gonna put this
in the oven.
Cilantro and relish,
tomatoes,
Korean chicken...
I'm gonna go
with the idea
that the plate
might be a bit small.
...guacamole, sour cream,
fusion sauce...
So if you want
to get this,
order on a Thursday
for Sunday.
...sesame seeds.
This is the salsa
that's served with it.
And?
And a partridge
in a pear tree.
Would you like a fork?
You can't eat nachos
with a fork.
That's crazy town
right there.
You got acid,
umami, creamy,
salty, meaty,
cheesy, bean-y.
That's a lot.
That's a lot of Yee's.
You are putting
so many flavors together.
I was a bit worried...
I figured.
...they were gonna compete.
They're playing
well together.
This is like a multicultural
playground,
and there's a lot
of different games going on.
That right there was
dodge ball hopscotch.
[ Laughs ]
When you look up
Mexican-Korean fusion
in the Flavortown library,
that's the picture
you'll see.
Four minutes
on the chicken.
We get nachos about once a week
so all the goodness
that goes with it.
Nachos with a fork,
is that legal in Juneau?
I don't know,
but the problem is
that I want to put more
of this in my mouth
than I can with my hands.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Two tofu tacos, order up!
V's is almost a hidden gem.
You walk through a door
of what looks like it would be
an office building
and go down the stairs
that almost look like a cellar.
GUY: How cold is it down here
in the winter?
I would think that it would be
frozen underground.
No, we have this new thing
called heaters.
So when did you give up
on the comedy career?
WOMAN #1: Feels comfortable,
lots of light, lots of color.
It's one of the places I like
to come just kind of hide away
from the rest of the world.
When we come back, we're
gonna make something else?
-Yes.
-Korean short ribs.
WOMAN #5:
I love the short ribs.
They've got kind of
a sweetness and a spiciness.
They should be
falling off the bone.
We'll see you in a bit.
We're at V's.
Something else.
Bye-bye.
Paint the walls,
making the sandwich,
can we get
both of them together?
Paint the walls.
Slicing.
See?
That's just how
"Karate Kid" started.
Welcome back.
"Triple D."
Hanging out with Hunter.
We're in Juneau, Alaska.
We found this funky little joint
in a basement
with this character
named Venietia Santana...
I want to eat them right now.
Ah.
GUY:
...the V behind V's Cellar Door
who's cooking up
a wild Asian-Mexican mash-up.
You can't go wrong
with anything on the menu.
Everything is delicious from
popcorn to nachos to short ribs.
Korean short ribs.
MAN:
You bite into the meat,
and then there's just
this wonderful Korean flavor.
The short ribs come
with the kimchi fried rice,
which is
my absolute favorite.
V, what's on the menu?
Short ribs.
They're out of long ribs.
Sorry.
First, we'll make
the marinade --
gluten-free soy sauce,
canola oil,
rice-wine vinegar,
garlic-chili paste.
Okay.
That's an aggressive whisk.
Now we're gonna put together
our bulgogi marinade --
sweet onions, sesame oil,
rice-wine vinegar,
pear, salt and pepper,
garlic, ginger...
Mary Ann.
...green onions...
More soy.
...apple, brown sugar.
Alright.
So coat it 2 1/2 hours.
What temp are we
gonna cook at?
375, 385.
Well, 390, 390, 395, 395,
not 400.
400, 400, 400, 400,
410, 410, 385.
Boom, sold.
We're gonna put together
our paste for our kimchi.
Okay.
Oyster sauce, gochugaru,
garlic, daikon,
green onions, water.
Salted,
rinsed napa cabbage.
How long
you let this set up?
Anywhere from 5 days
to 25 days.
Dig it.
Make the fried rice now.
It's kimchi rice.
It's not a fried rice.
Why do you call it
not a fried rice?
Because it's not fried as hard
as a fried rice.
Okay.
You go ahead with the rice,
fried rice.
Butter and oil...
That's not gonna
fry it at all.
...the kimchi...
Now the rice will go in
and not fry.
...salt and pepper, fusion
sauce that we made earlier.
Okay.
Ready.
Let's see it.
Our cabbage, which we serve
in our slow marinade.
It's rice-wine vinegar,
gluten-free soy sauce,
sambal and canola oil.
Got it.
Short ribs, fusion sauce
and sesame seeds.
First, I'm gonna try
the nonfried kimchi
fried rice,
which is dynamite.
I like the butter
in there.
Yeah, there's no dryness
in this at all.
Love the little tang
of the kimchi.
If you look at that short rib
the wrong way,
it'll fall apart.
Lot of balance.
Stabbed him.
Great soy, great spice,
great acid...
great fat.
Do you have any kids?
No.
Do you want one?
For sale.
Sesame seed these.
Just such a great mix
of flavors,
and I've got
the short ribs here,
which are
falling off the bone.
A lot of dance moves.
It's like V.
V does the dance moves,
and she does it.
Can I get
these two together?
VENIETIA: Nice and neat.
We eat with our eyes
way before we eat
with our mouths.
Everything is made with love,
and that's one of the things
I love about the food here.
If I had my way, I would simply
order one of each,
put it on the table and eat
off of everybody's plate.
Thanks for having us.
Thank you.
It was outstanding.
Now, did you that book
right over there, Hunter?
Good night.
♪♪
GUY: Up next on our
Juneau journey...
Inquiring minds
want to know.
...Philly cheesesteaks on
an Alaskan food trailer...
It's outstanding.
...and get the scoop
on a Cowboy Sundae.
Tower of savory goodness.
The tower of pain is what
you should be calling it.
♪♪
HUNTER: Whoa, an indoor gun
and archery range?
I just thought we
were going fishing.
No, son, we're not going here,
although that would be nice.
No, we're here to check out
a joint where this guy was born
and raised here in Juneau,
but he took off to Australia.
He's come back, and he's got
a food truck
people are
going crazy for.
This is Pucker Wilson's.
Good,
because I'm hungry.
But then
can we shoot the bows?
Then we can shoot the bows.
One Guac and Bawk.
Every time I order something,
I know it's gonna be fresh,
and it's gonna be delicious.
You got your pulled-pork
sandwich right here.
You just smell
the smoked meats.
GUY: And the man
behind the funky trailer
is chef and owner
Chad Edwards, not this dude.
Who is Pucker Wilson?
Inquiring minds
want to know.
I just thought it had
a nice ring to it.
Pucker Wilson is not
a real person.
No, it's not.
That's not Pucker Wilson?
Well, he is now.
Let me ask you this.
Who's that guy?
That's Pucker Wilson.
There's Pucker Wilson.
Boy, he must have been tall
if that's just his head.
Right.
The food is amazing.
He's got the staples.
I've got one Husky Dawson!
And then, of course,
he's got his daily specials.
Phillys are ready!
Wrap them up, D!
Philly cheesesteak is awesome.
Chad smoked the meat overnight.
It has peppers and onions
and secret sauce.
GUY: Nothing I love better than
a Philly cheesesteak
in a dirt parking lot
and a gun shop from a guy
that's from Australia
cooking here in Juneau, Alaska.
And that's never been
to Philadelphia.
That's country.
Right here on "Triple D."
Let's get into it.
So we're gonna make
our birch brine
to smoke our chuck roast.
What's up, chuck?
We take our birch syrup.
It's a lot like maple syrup,
but it's a bit richer.
This is Alaskan sea salt
from Sitka.
After seven days
on the brine,
we're gonna put it
on the smoker.
But before we do that,
we got to make a spritz.
Okay.
Margarine,
apple-cider vinegar,
soy sauce,
little umami...
He talked
about your mommy.
Hey, my mom.
...guava nectar and cola.
That's what we're
gonna spritz with?
Right.
And how long is it gonna be
on the smoker?
About 12 hours,
about 220.
We use hickory.
Look at that smoke ring.
Tender.
No question, there's a lot
of good flavor in that.
Peppers and onions here.
This is
rendered brisket fat.
I put bay leaves
in there.
I got you.
Now this is ready
for the flat top.
American cheese.
Good stuff.
Give it a little steam.
Is that
an actual trash-can lid?
It is, yeah.
That is your style
right there.
Ciabatta roll toasted
on both sides.
Cue the mayonnaise.
Got this mayo.
There we go.
That's a normal portion?
Yes, sir.
What happens when you don't
bring your kid
with you to eat it?
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
Thank you, hand.
It's outstanding.
What do you think
it is, Hunter,
that sets
this sandwich apart?
I want to see if my kid
has got his spidey senses on.
The sweetness of the peppers,
American cheese,
can't really go wrong
with that, juicy.
You got great texture.
It's super rich.
It's unconventional,
but I'll tell you what.
I would order it
and order it again.
Thank you.
Breakfast, lunch and dinner.
I was gonna say
I'll come back tomorrow, too.
Okay.
We can do that.
One Philly cheesesteak.
This is my buddy, Brian,
that helped build my house
a couple different times.
What do you think
of the Philly cheesesteak?
I just like the sweet
of the onions,
the spices in the meat,
the cheese, very creamy.
CHAD: Alright.
Chicken is done.
What happens
during the winter?
It's snowing sideways,
but we're open.
We're here to serve
the local communities.
MAN #2: Being open year-round
for a food truck in general
is a huge deal.
I've seen in the freezing rain,
people lined up
around the block.
One Cowboy Sundae!
The Cowboy Sundae is
a heaping pile of goodness.
Who can beat French fries
with sauce
and pulled pork
and coleslaw on top?
GUY: Alright. What else
you got up your sleeve?
I've got a Cowboy Sundae
that we serve.
So you even make a sundae
on Friday?
Yeah.
Just changing up
the whole calendar.
We're actually not open
on Sunday, so...
I'm so lost.
Now we're gonna make
some dry brine for our pork.
Hit it.
Caster sugar,
garlic powder, paprika.
Shouldn't you have
some castanets
when you say it or something?
Right, right.
Fennel seed,
chili powder,
black pepper,
Alaskan sea salt.
Nice.
The rub goes on.
They go straight
on the smoker.
How long are they
gonna go on the smoker?
Until they're done.
You know, that's a good
motto to work with.
You know, I mean, yeah.
For you, come on down,
and we'll cook them
until they're done.
I mean, I'd say roughly
about 8 hours.
Okay.
So now we got to make
some barbecue sauce --
ketchup,
chili sauce, onion flakes,
apple-cider vinegar.
More of that birch syrup.
Is that a popular thing
around here, birch syrup?
Quit birching about it.
It's popular around here.
Birch, birch,
that's all you do.
Black pepper, Santa Maria
barbecue seasoning,
Worcestershire sauce
as well.
I got to try this.
Here, Hunter.
That's...
It's an oldie
but a goody, folks.
That was good.
That's delicious.
It's tangy.
It's sweet.
The onion flakes
are different.
Cool.
Here's the pork butt.
Nice and fall apart-y.
That's a word, I guess.
I'm Jerry Fall Apart-y.
We got the bark,
great flavor on that.
Hand-cut French fries.
So funny when they
always say hand-cut.
I mean, what would you do,
cut it with your foot?
I face-cut these fries.
So this is
a rosemary-fennel salt.
Throw that on the grill.
Add a bit of that barbecue sauce
that we made.
Right on top
just like that,
our savory slaw,
barbecue sauce.
Reason we call it a sundae
is because of the height.
Tower of savory goodness.
The tower of pain is what
you should be calling it.
I'm chiseling off a side
of the avalanche.
Oh, look at that.
It's delicious.
I mean, of course the barbecue
has got to be great,
but what makes
it is the fries.
That and the coleslaw.
The combo.
Nice job, buddy.
Thanks, man.
WOMAN #6: The Cowboy Sundae
really holds
a special place in my heart.
It's one of the best dishes
on the menu by far.
Pucker Wilson smokes
his own pork,
and so I love
the pulled pork.
Now you know there's not
really a Pucker Wilson.
Yes, I do know.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to break it.
Please don't cry, kids.
I've been a big fan
from the beginning,
and I'll keep coming
until he shuts his doors,
which I hope is never.
Still don't get the name.
Think the guy is
a little bit crazy,
but you're
gonna enjoy it.
We'll see you in a bit
on "Triple D."
Great job, Chef.
Thank you.
GUY: Coming up,
one crazy family...
Are you elves?
Do you sleep?
...makes an Italian pizza...
Nice job.
...with their Alaskan roots.
So we lay out
the reindeer-sausage patties.
It's not something
I say every day.
♪♪
Alright, Hunter.
For our final stop here
in Juneau
and it's your birthday,
what is your favorite food?
Everything.
I mean...
No, it can't be everything,
Hunter.
What is your favorite,
the number one?
What does your brother think
is a food group?
Oh, you know what?
Pizza.
I'm taking you to a place
where it's a full family,
I mean, the son, the daughter,
the mother, the father.
They've got a funky
wood-fired pizza oven
in a trailer right across
from the cruise ships.
You're gonna love it.
This is Forno Rosso.
King crab pizza.
I'm from New Jersey,
the land of great pizza,
and I've never tasted
anything like this.
Pepperoni in the oven.
Juneau is not full of awesome
little pizza trailers like this.
No, this is the only one,
and we love it.
Probably because
the little trailer comes with
their big-time wood-fired oven
manned by the Kotlarov family,
who have become
multitask masters.
We still have our other jobs
still.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
How many jobs
does this family have?
What does everyone
else do?
Too many.
I work for a doctor,
and he works for Noah.
Noah Fisheries.
We went to Italy
for a work assignment.
We all fell in love
with the culture of Italy,
and we kept just, like,
making pizzas after that.
NAKENNA:
I got a margherita here.
What's makes this pizza
so special?
WOMAN #7:
The local ingredients.
Like, the reindeer pizza,
they get their sausage
from right here in Alaska,
and they use our local
hometown beer in the sauce.
The crust is nice and flaky,
very flavorful.
GUY: You make all the dough
in the trailer?
Yes, sir.
Alright. Let's see it.
Okay.
This is a poolish.
How long have you had
this starter?
Four years.
It's awesome.
Amen.
Yeast, flour.
We're gonna add water.
Salt will go in.
The olive oil is added
at the very end.
And now we're gonna
get into making pie.
Correct.
Which one are we
gonna make first?
The rein-beer pizza.
So what I love is
the entertainment
that you get in the back,
the full construction
sound and the beeping.
KYM: We are going to cook
reindeer sausage.
I never pictured reindeer
in the plastic bag.
I always just thought
they had horns
and walked around
in the field.
Oh, they were.
How do you know
how much reindeer
is in
the reindeer sausage?
It's about 60%.
And the rest of it is...
Pork.
HUNTER: Nice.
So we lay out
the reindeer-sausage patties.
It's not something I say
every day.
What does it taste like?
Caribou.
Oh.
Well, if you
ever had caribou...
Well, there you go
then.
It tastes very similar
to a breakfast sausage.
Breakfast sausage.
Yes.
Okay.
So we're braising in beer.
They're gonna taste
much better.
So that goes in the oven.
About 15, 20 minutes.
It's about 700 degrees
in there right now.
Crumble it?
I actually cut it
into small squares.
I can't get any
of the questions right.
What else is gonna go
on this pizza
besides the reindeer sausage
that tastes like caribou?
We don't know what caribou
tastes like.
It's a white sauce that I make
in the oven as well.
Okay.
Butter and shallots.
In the oven.
Butter is melted.
More beer.
HUNTER: That looks
quite refreshing.
Well, it did
until it got hot.
Yeah.
Heavy cream
and a little salt.
Yeah.
That comes out, and it's time
to build the pie.
Yes, sir.
And more beeping.
Here we go.
So you get...
I'm gonna put these
in my car.
It's your
birthday present.
Ah, thank you.
There's our white sauce,
thin-sliced red onions.
Reindeer sausage.
Mozzarella, and this
is Jarlsberg.
It's moving.
Two minutes?
More like four.
Beautiful.
Hunter, I should've have
had her make one for you
being it's your birthday.
Very hot.
Very, very hot.
How do you do that?
I can't eat it that fast.
You bring it towards your mouth,
and you open your mouth,
and then you bite down.
Crazy.
What do you think, Hunter,
is the key to this pizza?
The red onion
and that sauce.
You can get all that beer flavor
in there.
It all kind of goes together
super nicely and...
Super nicely?
Super nicely, it's a new word
that I think complements
the sausage really well.
I think you're right
on all of it.
It's part sausage pizza.
It's part fondue.
It's part French onion soup,
creamy, rich,
a little tang to it
coming from that white sauce
because of the shallots,
nice dough, tender, firm,
good chew, excellent,
really good pie.
WOMAN #8: The reindeer with
the amber beer, I just love it.
My granddaughter actually
worries about me
because she thinks
I'm on Santa's naughty list
because I'm eating reindeer.
Get that nice bite mixed
with the saltiness
from the reindeer sausage,
and then that cheese
just kind of smoothes it out.
Do you cook?
I do.
Evidently.
You just nailed that.
You're going for Food Network.
I see it.
Have him removed
right now.
And a name, please?
GUY: Are you only open
on the weekends?
Six days a week.
Six...
That's just
during the summer.
Are you elves?
Do you sleep?
Is there 12 more that
are gonna come out
of the trailer?
We're just crazy.
Kym works so hard to make sure
that the food is perfect.
Favorite thing?
Nakenna's favorite pizza.
Nakenna's special.
It's got the prosciutto.
It's got mozzarella, onions.
The basil is handpicked fresh
daily, and it tastes amazing.
So next pizza,
the family special,
what do you guys call it?
The Nakenna.
After your daughter,
Nakenna.
Right.
Let's see it.
Okay.
Canned Marzano tomatoes
from Italy,
Genovese basil,
smells amazing.
♪♪
Do you see
how he was ready?
You think
you're so funny.
His hand went in
to block it
because he knew
that the push was coming.
Sucks when they grow up,
and you can't get them
on the old dumb ones again.
Our simple San Marzano,
basil and salt sauce.
Basil, red onions.
The fresh mozz.
Dried basil and oregano,
olive oil, prosciutto.
Cooking pizzas and listening
to the beep beep.
Let's do it.
Look at that slice
right there.
♪♪
That pizza is fantastic.
Mm-hmm.
Nakenna has got it
going on.
I love
the prosciutto on there.
It's salty, creamy,
got a good texture,
the cooked-down prosciutto,
a little bit of cheese
not overdone, the fresh onion
shining through, you know,
getting a little bit
of that acidity, delicious.
Thank you.
Nice job.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Nakenna's special.
The cheese is really good,
just the right amount of sauce.
It's like every bite
just is wonderful.
NAKENNA:
The Tuscani truffle.
WOMAN #9: Forno Russo is the
best place for Italian pizza
in southeast Alaska,
maybe even all of Alaska.
Between your other three jobs,
being a mom, being a wife,
getting up in the morning
doing the pizza program,
I bet when the winter
gets here, you're like,
"Oh, thank goodness.
I can go to halftime."
Excellent job, Chef.
Thank you.
Excellent job.
Alright, Hunter.
Hurry up.
We got to get
to your birthday party.
I am not wearing this.
I am 23 years old.
This is ridiculous.
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
Happy birthday.