Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ready? Drumroll, please.
...it's a pizza lover's
paradise.
And there's nothing
wrong with that.
From Boston,
to Santa Fe, to Reno...
Good-looking pie.
...three totally different
doughs...
"Dough" ya know?
...all kinds of wild toppings...
Ah, it looks good.
...all out of bounds.
That is dynamite.
Plus...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
...a powerhouse take
on the BLT...
That's a monster.
...and wings that will
make your head spin.
This is kind of like
getting on the Tilt-A-Whirl.
The Tilt-A-Whirl connected
to a roller coaster.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
In New York City,
they've got Fifth Avenue,
and in, well, Beverly Hills,
you've got Rodeo Drive.
So, when you come here
to Boston,
you got to come
to Newbury Street.
That's where all
the fine shops are.
And when you're looking
for a place to eat,
what are you expecting?
Of course,
a wonderful fine café.
But not on "Triple D," no.
We're going to check out
a funky joint
that is using beer
to make their pizza dough,
and I hear it's the real deal.
This is
Dirty Water Dough Co.
Large Fenway Frank, order up.
The best pizza at definitely
at Dirty Water Dough.
-Boom.
-Yeah, Boston strong!
Dirty Water!
Dirty Water. Like,
that sounds really weird.
FIERI: Unless you know
Boston's dirty little secret...
Order up.
...going into Sam Sokol's brand.
Turn of the century...
Wow, we're going that far back.
The Charles River, which was
the main water supply,
got so polluted
that the water was undrinkable.
So they started putting beer
in their dough.
I mean, it gives the crust
almost like
a bagel-y soft inside,
and then you get
a nice crispy outside.
And there's nothing
wrong with that.
Let's see how it works.
This is special flour.
The wheat is actually milled
from the middle,
so it gives you a real nice
high protein and low ash.
Salt, olive oil, little yeast,
water, Dirty Water IPA.
We're going to mix this up
for two to four minutes on low,
and then another six
to eight on high.
Then we let it rest.
Portion it out.
12-ounce?
I usually do 20s.
Oh, hey.
You want to do the big boys?
You want to do the little guy?
Whatever you want
to do, baller.
Want to do the babies
or big boys?
Let's see how good
he is on his 20.
Oh!
17.15.
Oh, oh, whoa.
20.25. Not bad.
Let them proof overnight.
What are we going to make?
We try to do some crafty,
fun stuff.
Eight minutes
on the Dirty Taco.
WOMAN: If you're going to marry
tacos and pizza,
then this is certainly
the best.
WOMAN #2: It has, like, lettuce,
chips, and then sour cream.
So there's, like,
a lot of different
texture combinations going on.
Are taco pizzas big
in Boston?
No, that's a --
That's a creation we created.
All right,
let's get into it.
We have our red sauce, oil,
onions, garlic, oregano,
pepper, salt,
a little bit of fennel.
Red chili flake.
And got to get a little kick.
All right.
Crown peeled tomatoes.
Our water.
Cook it on medium high
for about 20 to 25.
What else
for the Dirty Taco?
Meat. Let's make the meat.
Olive oil, chopped onions,
ground beef.
80/20?
That's it.
And you got your paprika.
Granulated garlic.
Pepper, salt, enchilada sauce.
Give it that nice taco smoke.
Cook this down, but let it cool
in its own juices,
and you'll get all that flavor
on top of the pizza?
You got it.
Semolina flour's the game,
huh?
Gives this some nice, great,
sweet flavor.
I like your technique.
Light sauce.
That's the most unconventional
saucing of a skin I've seen.
We're not a conventional
joint, Guy.
Shredded mozz,
yellow cheddar.
Now for the taco meat.
And the oven.
How long
is this going to take?
Eight minutes.
♪ Dun-da ♪
That's a big pie.
Ah, it looks good.
SOKOL: All right, lettuce,
diced tomato,
nacho cheese chips,
sour cream swirl.
It looks the part.
Beautiful.
♪♪
The crust is dynamite.
It's toothsome.
Got good pull.
I get the yeastiness out of it.
It's delicious.
I mean, as you can tell,
I didn't like it at all.
My son Ryder, he's gonna lose
his mind on this one.
RYDER: Hey, Dad.
Good morning, Ryder.
So, what are your two
favorite things
that you ask
for dinner all the time?
Tacos and pizza.
Check it out. Ready?
Drumroll, please.
A taco pizza.
Bring it home.
[ Laughs ] Mmm.
It's crunchy
like a taco,
cheesy like a pizza,
and the cool lettuce,
and then the sour cream
all over the top.
All right, I'll bring one home.
Love you, bub.
Okay. Love you, too.
I knew he would love it.
Bro, you smashed it.
Well done.
[ Bell dings ]
WOMAN: I love tacos,
and having all the components
on a pizza,
it's just amazing.
MAN: You do have the smoky
flavor from the meat.
Everything just comes together
very beautifully.
What else do you like
besides taco pizza?
-The buffalo chicken.
-Mac and cheese one's banging.
Mac and cheese. Order up.
Favorite pizza?
I'd say the Steak 'n Cola.
Steak 'n Cola.
Ready to finish, you guys.
The steak is really good.
It's marinated with cola,
which sounds weird at first,
but once you try it,
it's delicious.
Steak 'n Cola pizza?
I was looking at unique,
creative ways to marinate steak.
This is shredded,
not ground beef.
Correct.
Italian dressing.
And now we put the cola.
I'm just as freaked out
as you are right now.
Little soy sauce.
Granulated garlic.
Pepper.
And some salt.
You want to mix it up.
Marinate it good.
So, just a little bit
of provolone.
Got your mozz.
Why is it always my mozz?
I don't have any mozz here.
I can't check that
with my baggage.
And then you've got
your marinated steak.
It's my marinated.
Put it on raw.
Cola, the soy sauce,
and the Italian dressing.
My new favorite combo.
All mixed up.
You might be the one
that's mixed up.
We'll see about this.
Gorgonzola.
A little funk right there,
huh?
Your caramel-ized onions.
"Caramel-ized"?
So, the nice sweet onion.
[ Laughs ]
Put it in the oven
for eight minutes at 550.
♪♪
All right.
Right balance of
cheese and meat and sauce.
Not soggy.
Bro, you got a pizza here.
It's meaty.
It's rich and delivered
on a crust
that is up there with
some of the best I've had.
Chewy, yet tender.
It's not overdone
with the ingredients.
The attention to detail
is really paying off,
because I thought it's either
going to be a hero or a zero.
That's a hero.
That's a dynamite pie.
Here's a large
Steak 'n Cola.
WOMAN: It's just wonderful.
You want your pizza
to have some oomph to it.
The bold Gorgonzola,
the strong provolone.
It actually complemented
the sweet cola
of the steak
really well.
Unique and different.
Something I've never had before.
I would say
everybody's got to try it.
All day in the weeds, guys.
You're missing out if you
don't come to Dirty Water.
I love your creativity.
I love the fact that
in the middle
of Boston Rodeo Drive,
you're serving real-deal pie.
This is the place to go to.
Well done.
Thank you, Chef.
FIERI: Up next, outrageous pie
with Santa Fe
written all over it.
FIERI:
Fresh-made mozzarella,
house-butchered pig
bacon, sausage making.
And a crazy twist
on a standard sandwich...
Has anybody ever heard
of a BLT like that before?
Nope.
...packed with a powerful
pork punch.
You are a dangerous man.
Thank you very much.
♪♪
So, I'm here in the beautiful
high desert
of Santa Fe, New Mexico.
Now, if you've been watching
"Triple D" for a while,
you know that I love to throw
in my music references.
I'm always talking
about Metallica,
AC/DC, Kid Rock,
and Lynyrd Skynyrd.
So when I hear there's a chef
that's all about farm to table,
and he's got a restaurant
where the name
kind of plays a little homage
to one of my favorites,
Motley Crue, you know,
I got to check it out.
This is Dr. Field Goods Kitchen.
♪♪
You got New Mexican
pulled pork outside.
Come get it.
It's good comfort food,
and sometimes
you just need that.
The Brussels are down.
Everything is made from scratch,
locally sourced.
I dig it.
All put together
by Josh Gerwin,
who's blazing his own trail
as a "Josh"-of-all-trades.
Where'd the pizza
oven come from?
I built it.
And you're not just doing
pizza in there?
No. We do some mussels and
bread pudding and some steak.
Fresh-bake your bread?
Yes, sir.
Butchering whole animals.
I have a full-blown butcher shop
about five doors down.
Really?
Yeah. We bring whole hogs in.
Right.
We got the belly
that's going to make our bacon.
FIERI: Which goes into
a classic sandwich
with a not-so-classic style.
Josh's twist on the BLT.
It's a whole burger of bacon,
which certainly I've never heard
of anywhere except for here.
The mayo and the freshly baked
bread -- It's just delicious.
What are we going to make?
Bacon.
All right, man.
Let's get into it.
Brown sugar.
Fresh-ground black pepper.
Pink salt, kosher salt.
How many bellies you guys
doing in a week?
8 to 12.
So no 9, 10, or 11?
Well, 'cause two
come per pig.
I'll be over here.
Cure our pork belly now.
7 to 10 days.
What are you smoking it with?
Applewood.
Four to six hours at 116
till it gets a nice mahogany.
I grind it and make
a 9-ounce patty.
You give them 9 ounces
of bacon on this thing?
Well, and the lean meat
that binds it together.
This, I got to see.
Beautiful bacon, dude.
Put that on the grill, right?
Yeah. No kidding.
Can I just have this on a stick?
All that effort to make
this great bacon,
and now we're going
to grind it up.
Yeah.
And then make the patty,
and we're done?
Pretty much. And then I season
it was some kosher salt,
and white pepper.
Cook it in a wood-fired oven.
You make the bread, also?
Yeah. Potato bread.
It's like half potatoes
and half flour.
Boiled russets.
This is
more potato than bread.
I've never seen potato
bread at this level.
We go in with our water.
Fresh yeast -- super-critical.
Some olive oil.
A.P. flour. Bread flour.
Salt.
Mix it for about 12 minutes.
Let it proof for about an hour
till it doubles in size.
Portion it out.
Roll them out
into the kaiser shape.
Let them proof and
approximately double in size.
What temperature you
going to make it at?
350. About 20 minutes.
Okay.
Toasted kaiser.
Get a little bit
of mayonnaise on it.
Nice heirloom tomatoes.
Gorgeous.
Some organic greens.
Tiny bacon patty over here.
I've never seen that
much bacon on a BLT.
Top it with our kaiser for you.
House-made onion rings.
You ready?
♪♪
That's a monster.
Well, this is what everybody
wants a BLT to be like.
You're getting the volume
of a burger,
the flavor of the bacon,
the whole top of that patty
is just all that crispy,
crunchy, unctuous flavor.
Then, on the inside,
it's super-tender.
It's just done perfectly.
I mean, it's BLT
of another level.
You are a dangerous man.
Thank you very much.
BLT ready.
It's big mouthfuls
of juicy bacon
every time you bite into it.
That freshly made bread
is what takes it over the top.
Has anybody ever heard
of a BLT like that before?
Nope.
Most people's reactions
are in shock.
They're like,
"Where's the bacon?"
And they're like,
"Well, that's --
that's the patty right there."
It is ridiculous, right?
Fire kale salad.
He takes farm to table
to a whole nother level.
He uses New-Mexico-grown produce
and meats from local farmers.
FIERI:
So the name Dr. Field Goods
totally makes sense.
Plus, it's a nod
to a rocking album
that goes with Josh's
heavy-metal attitude.
I'm a huge Motley Crue fan.
So the name fits for me
right off the bat.
Right.
WOMAN:
I love that he's unapologetic
about his really loud rock music
he plays in the restaurant.
Really good energy and fun vibe.
You got any other tricks
up your sleeves?
Carne adovada on a pizza.
The carne adovada is so good.
It's just a work of art.
You guys want pizza?
All right. Don't go anywhere.
Go check the e-mails.
Go feed the cat.
Take the dog for a walk.
Come right back, 'cause
you're going to love this.
Want a bite?
I'm good. You can have it.
You want me to play bone saw?
Yeah. Let's hear it.
Wuh!
That's all I have.
I just...
I look good holding it.
That's it.
♪♪
All right,
so, here we are, "Triple D"
hanging out in Santa Fe
with Chef Josh.
Dr Field Goods.
I love the name.
You got a butcher shop
down the street, farm to table.
MAN: He takes all of
this locally raised pork
and beef
and transforms them.
MAN #2: The chef takes
our local favorites
like the carne adovada,
and you put it on a pizza.
Pizza Margherita up.
Come get it.
It's pork marinated in chili,
and it's slow-cooked.
It tastes wonderful.
What are
we going to make next?
We're going to make
our pizza dough.
Water.
Fresh yeast. Local honey.
Olive oil.
High-gluten pizza flour.
Okay.
Iodized salt. Mix it.
12 minutes.
Proof it for an hour.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What are we into?
Fresh mozzarella.
I got to go.
Fresh-made mozzarella.
House-made dough.
Butchered pig
bacon, sausage making...
Mozzarella curds,
and we're going to pour
boiling salted water over it.
You're going to put
your hand in there?
Yeah. Good times.
We're stretching this out.
You're slowly letting this
come together.
Sticking your hands in that
hot water makes you sweat.
"You can do it, Rocky."
Thank you.
And then you'll form
this into...
Mozzarella balls.
Drop it in the ice water.
What do we have left?
Carne adovada.
So, we got pork shoulder.
Yeah, let it sear.
Okay.
Season it with salt.
Get it nice and brown.
Gets it a little richer.
Sweet smoked paprika.
Hot smoked paprika.
Red chili flake
for some bite.
Boy, you can pick that up
real quick.
House-made red chili sauce.
And what do we have in that?
Pat's red chili,
garlic, onion.
Water.
Cook this down?
Six to eight hours
till we're nice and tender.
All right, Chef.
Pizza dough. Roll it out.
No one's ever hit the ceiling.
Never.
Olive oil.
House-made mozz.
Heirloom tomato.
Now we're just showing off.
Tomatoes are ridiculous.
They are amazing tomatoes.
Load up the carne adovada.
Oh, bro, it's cold,
and it's fantastic.
Just the right amount of heat.
Little salt.
Little white pepper.
Fire it in.
What temp are we
running this oven?
700 to 900 degrees.
Got it.
6, 10 minutes.
Gorgeous.
Got to have that chiffonade
of basil on a pizza Margherita.
Fresh olive oil on the crust.
Now it's ready for you.
Whew!
That bad boy is hot, hot, hot.
♪♪
It's definitely
my favorite pizza.
It's not lacking any flavor.
Let me tell you that much.
♪♪
The adovada marries
with the sauce, the olive oil,
and the tomato
breaking down.
That crust is super-light,
really thin, but it holds up.
Real artisan.
That is dynamite.
Margherita carne adovada.
It's got just
the right amount of spice.
It's not going
to ruin your day.
I love the smokiness
of the mozzarella
and, also, mixed
with the red chili,
and the crust is to die for.
Just amazing. It's a great place
to come and hang out.
Yeah, it's one
of my favorite spots.
It's just an experience
on its own.
Bro, when you talk about
being Dr. Field Goods,
you are absolutely
representing the name correctly.
Nicely done.
Thank you.
Dynamite food.
FIERI: Coming up...
The best pizza ever!
Can this guy do my voiceovers,
please?
A Reno joint putting
their own stamp on pie.
It is fantastic.
...and proving why
their wings are winners.
If you want a wing that has
more flavor in one wing
than most dozen wings,
this is your wing.
♪♪
Now, my son Ryder,
he believes that pizza,
well, is its own food group.
So, whenever we roll
into a new town,
we're asking everybody
right off the bat,
"Where is the real-deal
pizza joint?"
Well, I'm here in Reno, Nevada,
and I didn't have
to ask many people.
Everybody said, "You got to
check out Noble Pie Parlor."
Got a slice of pepperoni
and sausage.
This is, like,
the best pizza ever!
Can this guy do my voiceovers,
please?
I need cheese
on the meatballs.
Everything they do here
is wonderful.
FIERI:
And the story here begins
with co-owner Ryan Goldhammer's
time in front of the tube.
I started off by watching shows
like yours.
Well, that's probably...
So, started watching
Food Network
when I was about
10 years old.
And you taught yourself
how to cook?
Taught myself how to cook.
We've got
one order frachos.
Ryan's always making moves,
and once Trevor Leppek
got partnered
together with that,
they kind of became
a powerhouse.
That pizza over there actually
is named
after Trevor -- the T-Pane.
MAN: It's got sausage,
which is made in-house;
Pecorino cheese; apple;
and the caramelized onion.
There's something
about that crust.
It's just addicting.
Was this once
the manager's office?
This is the dough room.
"Dough" ya know?
So, we've got
our live active yeast
that we added
to our apple juice.
Reno water. Reno has
very high mineral content.
More minerals to munch on.
Mineral munching here
on "Triple D."
Ice.
High-gluten, high-yeast,
high-ash flour.
Low-protein flour.
We still have to add salt
to this.
How long is this going to run?
For about eight minutes or so.
Okay.
Proof for 24 hours.
Ball them up.
Proof for another 24 hours.
Got it. And what kind
of pizza are we making?
We're going to be making
the T-Pane pizza,
which is named after
my partner Trevor Leppek.
So, they called him T-Pain.
How'd it get to T-Pane?
Pane -- bread. Italian.
It's your little more
for it.
Absolutely.
Got it.
So, we're going to do
our sausage slurry.
So you're making your
own sausage, as well?
Absolutely. We slice it,
dice it, roast it, toast it.
That should be
on a T-shirt.
All right,
let's get into this.
Fresh fennel, garlic,
black pepper,
cumin, coriander,
star anise powder.
Really?
Yep.
Red pepper flake, salt,
a little bit of water.
Give another pulse.
Basil.
And this is going to get
worked into the meat.
And we cook this for 20,
25 minutes.
Okay.
All right. We're going to
make our T-Pane mix.
Olive oil, fresh fennel,
peeled onion,
Granny Smith apple,
lemon juice, ground star anise.
Got to like
that ground star anise.
Red pepper flake, cumin, fresh
garlic, salt, black pepper.
Okay.
Cook for at least 30 minutes.
All right, let's see it.
First going with
our Brooklyn red.
What's in the tomato sauce?
Fresh tomato fillet,
crushed puree,
sautéed onions, garlic,
and a little Madeira wine.
Okay.
Italian seasoning,
dry parsley,
garlic powder, onion powder,
a little bit of olive oil,
a little bit of salt,
and some fresh basil.
Got it.
Crown it.
Whole milk mozzarella,
pork sausage that
we made earlier,
our T-Pane caramelized mixture.
Right.
Sharp provolone, Pecorino,
apple,
and a little bit of mozzarella
there, and we're ready to go.
Good-looking pie.
We've got two ovens.
We're throwing the hot side
at about 625,
and then we go
to our cooler side,
which is about 590 to 600.
Got it.
Roasted garlic, olive oil,
Italian seasoning.
Okay.
We're ready to rock.
♪♪
Wow. That dough
is one of the best.
The texture of
the dough's fantastic.
The flavor is yeasty, rich.
The crunch of the fennel
and the apple.
The house-made sausage.
The subtle tomato sauce,
not overly acidic.
Super-in-balance.
It is fantastic.
T-Pane.
Fabulous. I really do like
the contrast
between the sausage
and the apples.
MAN:
It's a Wonkavator of flavor.
It goes up, down, left, right,
absolutely everywhere.
All right,
Zeppe's going out.
Reno is pretty amazing.
We have this whole resurgence
of Midtown,
and Trevor and Ryan
have been such a huge part.
MAN: This spot, five years ago,
there weren't restaurants,
there weren't
nice dive bars.
Did you say
"nice dive bars"?
My kind of place.
I like the nice dive bar.
Yeah, yeah.
We usually come here
probably every other week,
and we have to have
a pizza and the wings.
I have
the 2 pounds of wings.
Wings are no joke.
Just enough spice.
They toss it in that sauce
that they have,
and then, with the scallions
and the cheese on it,
it's just perfect.
What's so special
about the wings?
The Biggest Little Wing Fest
here in Reno
is the third-largest wing
competition in the world,
and we took first place.
Get it!
So, we're going to make
our wing sauce.
Butter, cayenne pepper sauce,
ketchup, sriracha, raw garlic.
Bunch of it.
Worcestershire.
Worcestershire [Mumbles]
[ Mumbles ]
Cayenne,
garlic salt, and sugar.
Let it simmer for about
30 minutes or so.
And then we add
our sour cream.
Sauce is done.
Time for the ranch.
Yeah.
Heavy-duty mayonnaise.
Not light duty here,
folks.
Buttermilk, sour cream,
Worcestershire.
[ Mumbles ]
Lemon juice, garlic,
green onion, some dill.
That's a big "dill."
Garlic powder, onion powder,
paprika, parsley,
garlic salt,
salt, and pepper.
And Parmesan cheese.
Mix it up.
Good ranch.
Tell me about the wings.
They are a parbaked wing.
Great.
Then we fry them up.
We usually let them sit
for a little bit,
kind of give them
a double fry.
So, we're going in
with our sauce,
in with the wings,
a little more sauce,
and then get just
really nice coated.
Parmesan cheese,
garlic, some green onions.
And the house-made ranch.
♪♪
If you want a wing
that has more flavor in one wing
than most dozen wings have,
this is your wing.
There's a silkiness
about the sauce.
There's a little bit of heat.
Love the sour cream
into it.
Genius move. I love
the little double fry on it.
So, if you think of a wing
with hot sauce,
a little bit
of butter in it,
and there you go,
and I'm going to fry it up,
that's kind of like riding
the merry-go-round.
This is kind of like
getting on the Tilt-A-Whirl.
The Tilt-a-Whirl connected
to a roller coaster.
Dynamite.
-Pound of wings.
These have a perfect crisp
on the outside.
It's a nice sticky sauce,
so the fresh garlic
sticks to it.
The Parmesan sticks to it.
The green onions.
The Ranch and Noble pie
is 100% amazing.
You can tell it's homemade.
Meatball sliders.
They take something that
is staple to the next level.
Noble Pizza Parlor.
Real deal.
Good job, Chef.
Thank you.
So, that's it for this road
trip, but don't worry --
We got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
We'll see you next time
with Guy Fieri,
and we're looking for you.
We're coming to your town.
We know where you live.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Cut!