You know, people were asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy. That one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is
ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like, on this trip,
a joint outside Kansas City...
Pork belly
burnt ends!
...cranking out
killer 'cue...
-Look at all the juice.
-Oh, yeah.
Mmm.
GUY: ...and teaching me
a thing or two.
Really?
I learned one today.
And in Phoenix, Arizona...
You see this?
...Chinese and Mexican meet...
I am just in awe.
...for the ultimate
"Triple D" mash-up.
It's like a ketchup hot tub
in Flavortown.
Plus, in San Diego,
we're busting down doors
to get back to a diner...
This is delicious.
...where I get to be
on the right side of a raid.
That was crazy.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
You know, I have traveled
all around this country
and out of this country
looking for the greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives,
and I got to be honest with you,
folks, there aren't as many
diners as there used to be.
So, I'm here in San Diego
about 15 minutes
from downtown to check out
a "Triple D" O.G. from 2007.
This is Studio Diner.
♪♪
I love the food,
and I love the people here.
MAN: It's the best old-school
East Coast diner
I've ever found
in Southern California.
GUY: That's because restaurant
owner and movie producer
Stu Segall brought his love
of diners with him
from Massachusetts.
Just between you and me, like,
the camera is not rolling --
Did you just build this
so you had a place to eat?
Yeah, I did. Look at at me.
I love to eat.
Yeah, it's
a championship belly.
There you go.
That's it.
I'm looking
for the boss.
What's up, buddy?
Hey, brother.
How you been?
Good. Good. Good.
It's been 12 years, and the show
was so new back then,
I didn't realize how few diners
there were on the West Coast.
Not just the building,
but the energy,
the atmosphere,
the counter.
This is kind of its own
little unique oasis.
I love it.
Menu changed?
A little bit,
but not much.
It kind of more seems like
it's things you like
or that
your buddies like.
It should just say,
"Stu's."
Well, it does. Yes.
It does.
Still have
the clam bellies?
Oh, yeah.
Whole belly, Ipswich?
Ipswich.
It's a part of Massachusetts.
You have them flown here
three times a week?
Absolutely.
Yep.
As long as people buy them
and eat them,
we'll keep
flying them in.
Ipswich clams.
Ipswich.
Ip...swich.
You got it.
Unleash the clam.
Getting drained.
These guys get rinsed off.
Buttermilk.
Then they're going to soak
in here for about a 1/2 hour.
Clams out
of the buttermilk.
What's the flour
mixture here?
This is fish batter.
You're just giving it
a light dredge?
Yes.
What's in
this fish batter?
Has it got a little salt,
a little seasoning in it?
It's almost like
a tempura base.
See, it's got a little bit
of a corn flouring to it,
lightly dredged,
not heavy packed.
Ipswich clams.
Ipswich, Mass.
Neither of us
have ever been there.
Never.
[ Laughs ]
Tartar sauce.
Full belly and all.
Yes.
♪♪
Mmm.
Very mild flavor,
but it is sweet.
Good clam.
GUY: Those classic clams were
the work of Johnny San Nicolas,
who started here
when Stu opened in 2003,
but when he passed away
a few years ago,
John Leonard carried
on the tradition.
How we doing
on those specials?
Plus, he's cooking new creations
like the lobster potpie.
Oh, is this it?
This is it.
LEONARD: Garlic and oil,
lemon, dry sherry,
lobster stock,
then heavy cream.
We reduce our lobster bisque
down for 45 minutes,
put peas and carrots,
our lobster bisque.
Now we're going to chop up
our Maine lobster claw,
and then top it
with our piecrust,
and we're going to bush it
with an egg wash.
Lobster potpie
for the bar.
♪♪
Great lobster bisque.
Tender peas and carrots.
There's texture
in the vegetables.
It's not
all blown out.
I'm so happy that I'm not
standing my fork up in it.
That's when you allow the crust
of that potpie to do its job
and work as that
thickening agent,
so it really
sops it up.
Yeah, you don't want a pasty,
you know, bisque.
You want, you know,
nice smooth, creamy bisque.
You got a really good hand
at not overdoing it.
It's delicious.
The pieces of lobster
are huge.
The lobster is real fresh.
It's very, very consistent
with what you'd have back
on the East Coast.
GUY: Same goes
for the Philly cheesesteak.
Samson's Steak Sandwich.
That's the one.
My dad's name was Sam.
And you're his son.
I'm the son, so it's
Sam's son's sandwich.
It's made
with prime rib.
So, you're going to trim
all the fat off of this?
All the fat off this.
We're going to slice it
thin as I can.
That would make
some money carpaccio.
Pineapple juice.
About a cup and a half
of soy sauce.
Garlic.
And we have sugar.
And a little black pepper.
Pepper.
Sesame oil.
Yes.
That smells great.
Take your meat,
place it in there.
I'm going to get
my veggies going.
Spinach, some onion, little
mushrooms, bean sprouts.
I learned this at Brint's Diner
in Wichita, Kansas.
It's the gentle
Frank Sinatra kick.
You just hit those
right on top?
Right on top.
We finish it
with some mozzarella.
Put it upstairs.
Let it melt.
That is just crazy.
Look at that.
That is one juicy sandwich.
♪♪
That meat is tender.
That's good, man.
That's really good.
Stir-fry meets
Philly cheesesteak.
Good combination.
It is.
It's a
great combination.
That is the funkiest cheesesteak
I've ever had.
GUY:
Served in a pretty funky diner
because Stu opened this place
right on his own studio lot.
So, all of this,
TV shows were...
SEGALL: These are all sets I use
in different TV shows.
So, over 900 hours...
About 900 hours, yeah.
...of television has been
shot back here.
Hey, an airplane!
Yeah.
It's a 727.
And after years
as a production set,
Stu offered up his studio
for military training.
I can make their training
extremely realistic,
and that's what these kids
are ready to go do.
And I see kids
respect it, honestly.
Hey, I really enjoy
your show.
Hey, thanks, brother.
Thanks for doing what you're
doing, man. This is crazy.
What's going on
in the studio in the back?
We don't do
anymore TV shows.
We're in military
and civilian medical
and civilian law-
enforcement training.
DEA is out back training
right now.
They're waiting
for you.
Awesome, man.
And when
we come back...
That is so awesome.
...I'm building up
an appetite...
This is how you
should serve a fillet.
...by breaking down doors.
"Diners, Drive-Ins & DEA."
GUY:
I'm at Studio Diner in San Diego
where diner owner
and movie vet Stu Segall...
Lobster roll.
Absolutely.
...built his East
Coast-inspired eatery
right on the lot
of this production studio.
Are these real?
Those are real.
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
take one.
Action.
[ Laughs ]
But there's
no moviemaking these days
because Stu is letting
law enforcement
and the military use it
for some tactical training.
I want to go see
the lot.
All right.
Let's go check it out.
DEA!
First one!
Move to your right!
That is so awesome.
So, you design a maneuver
that's going to take place?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
I'll put role players in there.
And then you do it,
and then you come back,
and you review
what happened and say,
"Okay, this is what
we did right."
Yeah. Yeah.
So, come and follow me.
Great. Great. Great.
♪♪
DEA! Police! Search warrant!
Open door left!
Door to the left.
You got someone with you.
Go ahead.
That was crazy.
♪♪
"Diners, Drive-Ins & DEA."
After that workout,
I'm ready to eat.
-That is...
-The gaucho steak sandwich.
It was a kind of a creation
of John Leonard's, the chef now.
LEONARD: What we're making here
is a house-made chimichurri --
cilantro, dried oregano,
smoked paprika,
garlic, red-chili flake,
salt and pepper, olive oil.
Now, we're butterflying
our tenderloin.
What we have here
is my chipotle cream.
It's chipotle, lemon juice,
garlic, sour cream,
salt and pepper.
Chimichurri, pickled onions,
wild arugula.
Gaucho steak sandwich
coming out.
Tastes like a Argentinean
steak sandwich.
There you go.
I'm not a fillet fan
because it has no flavor.
Sure.
But if you're going
to give a chimichurri
with it and arugula...
Yeah.
...in a nice crusty bread,
then I'm a fan.
This is how you should
serve a fillet.
Great sandwich.
Man:
Very tender and spicy,
which is what I like
in sandwiches, especially.
The chimichurri sauce, it's
sort of like a Latin flavor,
so it really complements
the whole dish.
I'm really glad you're
still here
because you were one
of the founding fathers.
You're one of the O.G.s
of "Triple D."
I know.
You come, and you light up
the diner world in San Diego
where no one would expect
to find a diner.
You offer a service.
You offer a great environment,
and people will come back to it.
See, that's why
you're still here.
We're lucky to have
guys like you.
Thank you.
I'll see you
before 12 years.
I hope so.
I'm going to see you next week
is when I'm going to see you.
I'm coming back.
Stu has got
a pretty sweet setup there
helping out
the country's finest
and serving real-deal
diner classics.
Now, to me, that's a win-win.
Now, coming up...
Oh, you think
it's popular now.
...another winning combo
when a French-trained chef...
Lamb ribs.
Yeah.
...hits
the barbecue circuit.
You're doing some crazy,
crazy barbecue.
Back in 2010, I drove
all over Kansas City
searching for some of
the best barbecue I could find.
I'm going to take you to some of
the places you'd drive right by
if you didn't have
the "Triple D" inside track.
And one place south of the city
in Mission, Kansas,
checked all those boxes.
Burnt ends.
They got killer barbecue,
off the beaten path,
and a chef
doing things his way.
We got to check out
R.J.'s Bob-Be-Que.
Denver lamb ribs up.
"Triple D" coming here
confirmed what I already knew,
that this is the best
barbecue joint in Kansas City.
I love the atmosphere here.
The food is wonderful.
They offer a wide variety
of items on their menu.
I've been coming here five,
six times a week
and have something
different every time.
It's just fantastic.
GUY: That's all thanks to owner
and French-trained chef
Bob Palmgren, who decided
to make his barbecue hobby
a full-time gig
back in 2003.
So, you do 25 years
of high-end restaurants.
Uh-huh.
When did you have this epiphany
to just say,
"That's it. I'm going to go do
my own barbecue joint"?
I mean, I've don't it
all already.
I just got
a little bored,
and I like barbecuing
and getting back to --
Back the the basics.
Yeah.
You do ribs...
chicken, pork,
brisket...
GUY: burnt ends?
You name it.
Lamb ribs.
Lamb ribs?
I don't know that I see lamb
ribs on many barbecue menus.
I try to lend
my French culinary skills
to make barbecue
a little different
than most other people
in the world do.
This is
a hellacious rub.
Corn dextrose, salt, basil,
cane sugar,
got to have chili powder
in a rub.
A whole mess of it.
You got it.
Vegetarian chicken base,
ground cumin.
He's like
speed-rub builder.
Yeah.
[ High-pitched ] Seasoning salt,
brown sugar, rosemary,
black pepper,
cayenne pepper...
For one rub?
Oh, yeah.
It really does have
like 35 ingredients in it.
We let these set
for at least 3 or 4 hours
or sometimes overnight.
Okay, so, these are going to go
in for how long?
Two and a half hours,
250 degrees.
Two and a half hours
at 250.
These look more like
a spare rib.
That's why they call them
Denver lamb rib.
It's the way
they cut them.
But they are coming
from down here?
Uh-huh. Yes, sir,
just like people.
Because I'm petite
like a lamb.
Just think of me
as a big lamb.
I'm mutton.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
Nice smoke ring.
The rub
doesn't overpower it,
sits there and
just kind of supports it.
Great stuff.
Nice job.
Thank you.
GUY:
And these days, Bob is putting
that multi-ingredient rub
on this newcomer.
Pork-belly burnt ends --
amazing.
We're going to put them
in the little bit of the rub
that I made with Guy
last time.
Wow.
And then we'll smoke it
for about 2 1/2 hours,
put them in a sauté pan
with a little bit of butter
and onions in there,
kind of getting them
a little crispy, finish it
with our Southern sauce.
Drizzle it with a little bit
of honey on top,
garnish it
with some fresh raspberries
and raspberry preserves.
Pork-belly burnt ends!
That savory, thick bark, and he
puts the raspberries on it,
which just sends it
over-the-top.
MAN:
And the interplay with the salty
and the sweet melts
in your mouth.
Pork-lover's candy.
All right, brother,
what are we going to do now?
PALMGREN: Now we need
the ground pork up
for the smoked
jalapeño sausages.
Pork butts are perfect
for sausages.
Packed with
their own fat.
That's right.
Ground pork butt.
A little bit of nutmeg,
fresh garlic,
cayenne pepper,
ground pepper,
and then allspice,
some jalapeños diced up.
Got a little bit
of sugar
to sweeten life up
a little bit here.
The old diced
red peppers.
Nice color.
And then you got
your corn husk.
Really?
He goes, "Well,
I'm from California,
and I've never seen
anything like this."
Holds moisture in
for a tamale,
but it'll let smoke
through for sausage.
And keeps your sausage
moist, too.
We're going to roll it up,
twist each end here.
This is going to take
about an hour and a half.
These should pop
right out.
Look at
the smoke ring.
Look at all the juice.
Oh, yeah.
Mmm.
It's super tender.
Don't eat
the corn husk.
I work with corn husk, okay?
I make tamales.
I learned one today.
I'm going to politely tell you
that I will be ripping off
the "corn-husk sausage" idea.
I've always wondered
after 9 years.
I bet he did steal that recipe.
How many pounds of this
will you do a week?
About 100 pounds.
It's growing in popularity.
I'm telling you.
Oh, you think
it's popular now...
Oh, yeah, I know.
...just wait.
Since "Triple D," a lot of
people from all over the world
have been here,
and we've got books to prove it.
We've continued to grow
our business here.
Got the patio out back,
full bar downstairs,
expanded his catering --
tiny empire that
he's starting to build.
GUY:
And with it comes new recipes
like the bison empanadas.
PALMGREN: We're going to brown
our bison up a little bit,
add a little salt, cracked black
pepper, get a little onion,
fresh chopped garlic,
jalapeño, diced tomatoes.
Usually, they use raisins
in empanadas.
We use craisins.
Cumin, cinnamon, and cloves.
Let it simmer
for about 5, 6 minutes.
Let it cool down, and then
we'll make up the empanadas.
Then they'll be ready
for deep-frying.
Garnish it with baby arugula
and chipotle mayo,
five empanadas,
sprinkle a little paprika on it.
Bison empanadas, table 14.
There's just the right amount
of breading on it --
nice and flaky,
and it's packed with
a lot of spicy, seasoned meat.
WOMAN:
When you took a bite,
they just kind of explode
in your mouth,
like, zip in your mouth.
I just love it.
You're doing some crazy,
crazy barbecue.
Thank you.
Come back and see us anytime.
Don't worry.
I ain't going to be able
to get a seat in this place.
Yeah.
It's like Yogi Berra said,
"That place?
No one goes there anymore.
Too damn crowded."
♪♪
Sausage cooked
in a corn husk?
Now, that was one
for the books.
And coming up, something else
you don't see every day...
I feel like I went through
food boot camp.
...Chinese food colliding
with a Mexican menu.
This is like a food hurricane.
[ Laughter ]
I'm sure everyone knows by now
that I am a sucker for,
"A," great Chinese food,
and, B, great Mexican food.
Back in 2008 in Phoenix,
Arizona,
I happened to find a place
that was dishing out
both on the same plate.
I know.
[ Imitates explosion ]
Mind-blowing.
This is Chino Bandido.
Jerk-fried rice plate.
Jade Red Quesadilla combo.
It's your typical
Mexican-Jamaican-Chinese place.
[ Laughter ]
I don't know why they work
together, but they do,
and if I tried
to put it together,
it wouldn't taste like this,
but Eve manages
to make it taste amazing.
GUY:
She's talking about Eve Collins,
who started this joint
with her husband,
Frank, back in 1990.
Chinese food
in a quesadilla.
Sadly, Frank passed away
in 2013,
and, man, I got to tell you,
everyone misses Frank.
Larger-than-life kind of guy.
Amazing sense of humor.
Guy met his match
when he met Frank.
Get away from me.
Let me show you
how to do it.
Your 30 seconds is
almost up.
All right, well,
they should have some food
out here pretty quick.
Are you sitting with me?
I'm going to sit with you
for a few minutes!
You get 96,420
different combinations.
I am lost.
-The menu is confusing...
-Cuckoo!
...unless you had Frank
explain it to you.
All right, I'll make you
an expert at Chino Bandido.
Combination is any two
of these numbers.
Mark your beans --
black or refried.
Mark your rice --
white, jerk-fried, pork-fried,
plain fried, and chicken-fried.
"B" is burrito,
"Q" is quesadilla.
Once you understand,
you're in the club.
I feel like I went through
food boot camp.
GUY:
It was exhausting, but I finally
settled on the Jade Red Chicken.
What are we making?
Red sauce
for Jade Red Chicken.
Tomato sauce.
Right into the oil.
Do you see this?
Then we put
the garlic in.
The oil --
Into.
Why?
It forms a glaze.
Looks like a ketchup hot tub
in Flavortown.
This is unlocking
Chinese secrets!
Powdered sugar?
Powdered sugar.
You let that boil.
Pop the green onions in.
I am just in awe.
And that'll boil down.
[ Whistles ]
So, we have thigh meat,
egg whites, cornstarch.
A little garlic salt.
You put it in there versus
in the cornstarch?
Yes.
Shake it up.
Ohhh!
Pop it over here,
and drop it in.
Isn't that pretty?
Okay, so, now we get
the sauce we made.
Right. When
it's boiling hot,
we're going to take
this chicken.
Wear, like,
a jumpsuit next time.
Yeah.
You only look like you've done
that 900,000 times.
Yeah. That's
your red chicken.
Ohhh!
That's going to be hot.
That's very hot.
Oh! It tastes like
sweet-and-sour chicken.
That's awesome.
1 down, 96,499 to go.
We give a half a dozen samples
to all the newbies.
Next, I'm going to give you
jerk chicken.
He gave him
every single thing.
Chug-a-lug that.
Chug-a-lug?
Open your mouth,
pretend like you're home,
and just chug it.
I'm full.
Oh, I know you're full.
That's okay.
This is all made with fresh
vegetables, bean sprouts, pea.
He even made him eat...
[ Record scratches ]
An egg.
You betcha.
...the egg foo young...
Real egg.
...knowing that Guy Fieri
does not like eggs.
You'll love it.
Just like that.
Is it possible just
to get foo young?
[ Laughs ]
GUY: These days,
Eve is still cranking out
all those killer combos...
Hen, 13Q.
...including
this fan favorite.
Try the emerald
chicken next.
Mm, the ginger...
Emerald chicken is one of
our best sellers.
First, we pound out
our chicken breast
so that they'll cook
nice and evenly,
and then we marinate it
in teriyaki sauce,
put it directly into the rack
and into the oven.
Now, we're going to make
the emerald sauce --
fresh green onions,
fresh ginger, salt,
and a little vegetable oil.
So, now, we're going to make
jerk-fried rice.
We use dark-meat chicken,
put it into jerk seasoning
from Jamaica.
We're going to marinate it
for 24 to 36 hours.
After it's cooked,
it's chopped up.
A little bit of green onion,
jerk chicken,
and the white rice.
Oyster sauce.
That's all there is to it.
And then we place the emerald
chicken onto the rice,
ladle the sauce.
Jerk-fried rice
and emerald chicken.
MAN: The emerald chicken
with the jerk-fried rice
was insanely good.
There's a light Chinese
herbal flavor
all the way down
to downright Mexican hot.
I love how much ginger is in it.
The chicken is awesome.
I mean, I can just eat
the sauce itself.
Winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
After "Triple D,"
it was crazy.
This is like
a food hurricane.
We had a line all the way
down the street.
It was amazing.
Hopefully, it'll go on
for decades more.
It's remarkable.
It's probably one of
the neatest places
that we've shot
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Aww, thank you.
♪♪
Everyone sure does miss Frank.
He'll always be an unforgettable
member of the "Triple D" family,
along with Eve, who's holding
down the fort in Phoenix
with her creative
Mexican-Chinese combos...
Mmm.
...and Stu whose East Coast
diner in San Diego
is attracting
all kinds of crowds...
That was crazy.
...plus Bob in Mission, Kansas,
whose spin on barbecue
is still out-of-bounds.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
that's just the tip
of the iceberg.
We got plenty more places to hit
next time on "Triple D Nation."
So, that's it for this adventure
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
and watch out.
We might be knocking
on your door next.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Flavortown Army!