Hey everybody, I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out.
Looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins and dives.
This trip...
He's on a roll today, folks.
We're grabbing hard
to find flavors...
We've got tree bark,
wing of bat.
...at some pretty unique joints.
This is outside the box, man.
Like a South Indian spot
in Santa Fe...
If I lived here, I would
be here once a week easy.
...a dynamite deli in Reno...
Oh, you're getting
all fancy dancey now.
...and a funky find
near Boston...
Just when I think
I know what's going on,
I have absolutely no idea.
...making vegan truly
out of this world.
This needs to go places.
People need to have this
in their town. The bomb.
That's all right here right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
I'm here in Cambridge,
Massachusetts driving between
MIT and Harvard.
Got a lot of smart people
and a lot of construction
going on.
Anyhow, if you haven't
noticed on "Triple D,"
I'm featuring
a lot more vegetarian
and vegan restaurants.
I mean, they just keep
getting bigger and better.
I mean, they're almost
getting out of this world.
Welcome to Veggie Galaxy.
20 seconds on this bacon.
Cauli of the Sea.
You imagine a vegan diet
is sort of lettuce
and things like that,
but this is not it.
They use all the flair
that any diner might use
and then some.
Vegan Reubens.
You don't find many places
like this.
FIERI: Which is why Adam Penn
and Kathy Tanner
decided to open this joint
in the first place.
I had moved to the Boston area
and there were hardly
any vegetarian restaurants
around at the time.
I needed a place to eat,
so decided to open one.
Vegan meatball sub.
FIERI: And they decided to bring
in Chef Sam Ranger
who's getting creative
with his comfort cooking.
-Favorite thing on the menu?
-Mac and Stack.
So the Mac and Stack
is something really interesting.
They use a mac and cheese waffle
as the bun and tempeh bacon.
There's a seitan
chicken cutlet on there.
What can I say?
It's just wonderful.
FIERI: What is this dish
we're making?
We're doing a tempeh
bacon marinade
and this is going on
the Mac and Stack.
It is a tempeh that
we're turning into have
the flavor of bacon?
Yeah, 'cause it's,
like, raw tempeh --
Got it.
...so it's not a lot of flavor
going on right now.
Right.
Wouldn't it be great
if regular bacon
had slabs that size?
Olive oil, a little bit
of maple syrup,
orange juice, liquid smoke,
tamari, brown sugar.
One of my favorite
Rolling Stones' songs.
-Dried basil.
-They don't have that song.
Smoked paprika,
onion powder, garlic.
How long are we gonna
marinate the tempeh in this?
About 30, 45 minutes.
Put it on a sheet pan
and we're gonna bake it off.
About 45 minutes at 350.
Then it goes on the flat
top for service.
Yep.
All right.
What do we make after this?
Seitan chicken.
Not Satan's chicken.
Yeah, you got it.
So we've got
vital wheat gluten.
We have what?
Vital wheat gluten.
Getting introduced to a bunch
of ingredients
I don't typically use.
-Nutritional yeast.
-I use that.
Mashed up chickpeas, cumin,
a little bit of sage,
rosemary, onion powder,
salt and pepper,
garlic powder,
smoked paprika.
Thyme.
Tamari tomorrow?
-Olive oil.
-Boom.
Vegetable broth.
Then we knead it.
Oh, of course, we need it.
We've got a lot of people
coming in to have it.
Of course.
You've got it.
[ Imitates gunfire ]
He's on a roll today, folks.
A Kaiser roll.
Put it onto tinfoil, roll it up.
Twist off the end.
You're gonna boil it?
It's a vegetable stock,
rosemary, thyme, sage.
So anything that gets in there
also flavors it.
Then you'll slice it and then
go to the flat top with it.
We typically fry the chicken.
Just when I think I know
what's going on,
I have absolutely no idea.
Great.
Now we're doing our
mac and cheese waffle.
A little bit of elbow pasta.
-Pancake batter.
-This is our vegan house cheese.
What's in vegan house cheese?
Soy milk, nutritional yeast,
smoked paprika, corn starch.
Okay and onions.
We're gonna mix it all up.
I got up early and didn't have
a chance just to...
[ Laughs ]
...is it better?
Ladle the sucker on for
about two and a half minutes
and then flip it and another
two and a half minutes.
Holy hot mash, Batman.
It's like a volcano
in Veggie Galaxy.
-Now we're ready to plate.
-Let's see it, brother.
Our waffle, lettuce, bacon,
chicken, sriracha aioli.
[ Imitates popping sound ]
There it is.
What's that little sound effect
you gave us on that, was that?
[ Imitates popping sound ]
Nice, nice.
See you can even hunch
with vegan.
♪♪
To have a sandwich that's that
big with that much flavor,
if you didn't tell people
that was vegan,
I don't think they would
even question it.
Awesome.
I mean, it's really got a lot
of great flavor.
It's got a lot of texture.
It's a lot of creativity.
That chicken patty
is crazy, dude.
Glad you like it.
I get the smokiness of bacon
and the maple of the bacon.
The mac and cheese waffle
is spot on.
♪♪
Well done, brother.
Here's your vegan
Mac and Stack.
You have the crispy seitan
chicken which is awesome
and then you just have
that really just, like,
gooey mac and cheese.
It's the ultimate comfort food.
We've got a vegan Buffalo Mac.
From the outside Veggie Galaxy
looks like
maybe it's just
another restaurant,
but inside has
that classic diner look.
I grew up on Long Island.
I love diners.
I'm picking it up.
It feels like the Jetsons
opened up
a vegetarian restaurant.
Just a great environment
kind of brings you back
to the old days of a diner.
A real true diner. That's what's
great about this place.
All right.
What else you got for me?
It's a --
Don't tell me. Don't tell me.
When we come back, we'll see
what else he's got on the menu.
-I gotcha. I gotcha.
-Thank you.
Got a necklace on?
-Nope. [ Laughs ]
-[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" is hanging out
in Cambridge, Massachusetts
in a funky little joint.
Well, actually, it's an enormous
joint called Veggie Galaxy.
Veggie Galaxy is
the best vegetarian
vegan place
in the Boston area.
This place is just great
for an alternative to a burger.
FIERI: Which can be just
a different kind of burger.
Two Kendalls coming up.
WOMAN: The Kendall square burger
is an awesome vegan burger.
The patty itself
is black beans and corn.
There is an onion ring on it.
It has a really good sauce
on it, too. It's great.
All right, what are we into now,
my friend?
Now we're gonna make
a black bean burger patty.
Let's see it.
So we're gonna start off with
quinoa, black beans, and corn.
Sweet potatoes
peeled and boiled?
-You got it.
-A little cumino?
Cumin, parsley,
smoked paprika, salt, cayenne.
And a little sweated
red onion?
You got it.
Panko breadcrumbs.
These are gonna be formed,
pattied,
and finished on the flat top?
You've got it.
What are we gonna
serve it on?
On our homemade burger bun.
-You make it?
-Yep.
Oh, let's do that.
Flour, salt, sugar, yeast.
-Olive oil and warm water?
-Mm-hmm.
So we'll mix this up
10, 15 minutes?
You got it.
Let it proof.
We're gonna make some burger
buns by measuring out
3.4 ounces.
And what are we gonna
bake this at?
350 for about
eight minutes.
-Last step.
-Red pepper purée.
Got it.
Roasted red bell peppers,
cilantro, garlic, cumin.
You guys love your cumin
around here.
Oh, yeah.
-Salt and pepper, cinnamon.
-Cinnamon-amon-amon-amon.
Agave, chipotle, and adobo.
We buzz this down,
we're gonna add the olive oil
and the red wine vinegar.
The host's job is never done.
I better get a t-shirt
out of this.
Heat that up and make
a soup out of it.
Oh, that's good. All right, man.
Let's build this.
So bun down,
roasted garlic mayo.
We have our dressed arugula,
a bit of lemon dressing,
then our patty.
Nice fried onion rings.
Now the red pepper purée.
Well done, my brother.
♪♪
That patty right there
is gonna wreck some
frozen veggie patty business.
That's legit, bro.
The quinoa
is what makes that rock.
And, of course,
you get the creaminess
from the sweet potato,
a little snap in the corn,
creaminess of the black bean.
House-made roll?
There's a lot of texture.
There's a tremendous
amount of flavor.
A nice little roasted piece
coming through
with the red bell pepper.
This is outside the box, man.
-Delicious.
-Thank you.
One, two and three
for the last one.
So the Kendall square burger
is just one of those burgers
you see
and you just got to have.
The buy is great.
It holds the sandwich together.
Very tasty.
Butter up that Reuben. Yeah?
Whether you're a vegan,
vegetarian or omnivore,
there's a little bit for
everyone here.
Love this place.
Probably our favorite
restaurant, quite honestly.
Your barbecued
jackfruit sandwich.
Veggie Galaxy,
this needs to go places.
People need to have this
in their town.
-The bomb.
-Thank you.
-Well done.
-Appreciate it.
FIERI: Up next,
a Santa Fe joint making
South Indian specialties...
This is the kind of place
I wish I had in my backyard.
...from a killer crispy crepe...
This is a game changer for me.
...to a righteous hardy stew.
That's what I want to do
is jump right in it.
♪♪
Man, do I love where we're going
with food these days.
I mean, look at it,
you've got organics,
you've got farm-to-table,
and you've got
all these fantastic
ethnic restaurants
opening up.
Now, one of my favorites --
Indian.
And it's typically
Northern Indian.
So when you come here
to Santa Fe, New Mexico
and you find out
that someone has got
a Southern Indian restaurant,
you've got to check it out.
This is Paper Dosa.
Chennai chicken, table seven.
You don't have to go to India
to experience Indian food.
Paper Dosa
is as good as it gets.
Spring vegetable curry.
Paper Dosa is different
than most restaurants.
Bhel puri, pick up.
Even in India, it's uncommon in
the northern part of the country
to find really good
South Indian food.
FIERI: But search in Santa Fe
and you'll find
Chef Paulraj Karuppasamy
who, along with his wife,
Nellie is dishing out
the South Indian flavors
he grew up with.
What were you doing
in the United States
when you met your wife?
I started working
in San Francisco
in a South Indian restaurant
as a cook.
She was a waitress.
So that's how we know...
Is that how it happened?
South India is more based
on rice and lentils
and the spices are more subtle
in South Indian food.
I have a masala dosa.
A dosa is similar to a crepe.
And then there's
a potato filling.
I had South Indian friends
growing up
and their moms
would make me dosas
and this is the same flavor.
FIERI:
What are we gonna make?
And this is a lentil?
Yeah, lentil. I use a lot
of hands in this.
Well, don't use your foot
and we're good.
[ Laughs ]
Rice flour, water, salt,
a little sugar.
-That's our batter?
-Yes.
So what are we gonna
put in the dosa?
It's called
classic masala dosa.
Okay.
A little oil, mustard seed,
chana dal.
This is actually garbanzo.
And what they do
is they roast it.
Okay.
Cashew nuts, red chilies,
curry leaves,
tumeric powder, yellow onions.
Cook down for 45, like,
minutes.
So now we have boiled, peeled,
russet potatoes.
And I'm adding garam marsala,
cilantro, salt.
And the last thing we have
to do is make the dosa.
Yeah.
-Water.
-I've never done this, though.
So we're doing
this together right now.
Oh! They get a poncho.
Wait for, like, two minutes.
We're gonna add some masala.
This is clarified butter.
They call ghee, yeah.
Ghee.
That is pretty much ready.
Oh, an Indian quesadilla.
This is coconut chutney.
We also have a tomato chutney.
You might want to think
about a different plate size.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
I'm making a dosa messa.
This is a game changer for me.
If I lived here, I would be here
once a week, easy.
I mean,
it is really flavorful.
The crunch of the dosa
doesn't feel real heavy.
You're not eating
a big flour tortilla.
You've got some really
interesting chutneys going on.
It's also got a lot
of textural difference.
You get a creamy,
you get a spicy,
you get a crunchy,
you get a sweet.
I mean, there's just
a whole bunch that's going on
in just this
one little simple dish.
-Outrageous.
-Thank you.
Masala dosa.
You have a burst of spices
when you bite into it.
It's phenomenal.
I've tried South Indian food
in India.
I've tried it in New York.
I've tried it in San Fran.
This is really authentic.
This is really good.
So this is a must visit place
in Santa Fe.
What's your favorite thing
on the menu?
The lamb curry.
The lamb curry
is really incredible.
So many spices mixing with
the good high quality meat.
What we're gonna break
into now is a curried lamb.
-Chettinad Lamb Curry.
-All right, let's see it.
I'm going to marinate
this lamb stew.
Garam masala powder,
cumin powder,
chili powder, fennel powder,
coriander powder.
oil, curry leaves, some salt,
ginger garlic paste.
-Okay.
-Yogurt, mint, cilantro.
And how long are we gonna
marinate the lamb?
8 to 12 hours.
All right, chef.
This is the masala mix
for the lamb.
-Cardamom.
-Mace.
Mace that's on the outside
of the nutmeg?
-Exactly, right.
-Okay.
Do you know what is this?
It looks like some type
of a moss, tree bark.
Yeah. This is a lichen.
We've got tree bark,
wing of bat.
-Fennel seed.
-Okay.
Cumin seed, peppercorns,
bay leaf.
Star anise.
Cinnamon, coriander seed.
Coriander, and what is that
a little funky thing?
Marathi moggu.
Oh, that's what I was
gonna call it.
This is a kind of a caper.
-But dried.
-Poppy seed, curry leaves.
-Of course.
-And some red chilies.
So you give this
a nice little toast?
Yeah.
Where are you getting
all your spices from, chef?
From Albuquerque.
That's usually where I go
for my heavy Indian spices,
Albuquerque.
Add water.
And now we're gonna
build the dish.
Yeah.
-Fennel seed.
-Star anise.
Peppercorns, green cardamom.
Bay leave, clove, the mace,
the funky pod thing.
-Yeah, and cinnamon.
-Cinnamon.
Cumin, onions.
Okay.
Add a little salt, tumeric,
and it cooks for, like,
15 minutes
and then we add ginger garlic
paste, and then the tomatoes.
Then marinated lamb goes in.
The chettinad masala.
-That we made.
-Yeah.
So we're gonna stew
this down.
For, like,
one and a half hours.
And then we'll add
the cashew paste.
At the very end.
Now the lamb curry
is ready to taste.
Spice oil. Got it.
Daikon and carrot beets, mint.
Yeah. Cherry tomatoes.
That's it.
Now do you take the rice
to the lamb
or the lamb to the rice?
However you like it.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
That's what I want to do
is jump right in it.
I want you to think about
your favorite beef stew
when you were a kid
and then I want you to think
that your cousin from India
decided to make you
their family's version of it.
It's rich. It's hearty.
I'm getting spice.
I'm getting smoke.
I'm getting acid
and a little bit of heat.
It's all over the board.
-Thank you.
-But delicious.
Chettinad lamb curry.
So tender and melted
in my mouth.
You combine the sweet
and the spicy with the lamb
and rice together.
It's very tasty.
Dahi vada.
This is the only Indian
restaurant that I come to.
Okay.
I can understand why.
It takes a lot of effort to make
this kind of food fresh
every day
and I think that's what makes
Paper Dosa really different.
This is the kind of place
that I wish had in my backyard.
-Excellent.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Nice job, chef.
-Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up in Reno, Nevada...
Build it, brother.
...a firefighter
turned deli master...
That is a combo
right there, folks.
...blazing a trail of
standout sandwiches.
Overachiever.
Who's this fireman?
♪♪
I don't know what it is,
but everybody one way
or another wants to be
in the restaurant business.
Maybe it's because they worked
in the business during college
or maybe their family
was in the business.
I don't know, but we're here
in South Reno, Nevada,
where a guy that was
a firefighter
has now opened
his own restaurant.
I guess you could say
it's kind of like
out of the fire
and into the kitchen.
This is Yosh's Unique Deli.
Smoked tri-tip going out.
It's fabulous.
It's innovative.
Gobbler with lingonberries.
WOMAN: I eat here probably twice
or three times a week.
Josh does a really good job.
FIERI: Or Yosh as Josh Codding's
family calls him.
Who called you, Yosh?
My younger sister, she couldn't
really pronounce my name.
It's like he was born
to do this.
FIERI: Or at least born
into the right family.
My grandfather started
a deli in 1975.
This was, like,
Reno's first deli.
My mom and aunt
took it over from them.
FIERI: Then after battling
wildfires for six years,
Josh jumped in to take
his own shot at sandwiches.
Pork belly bahn mi.
Pork belly bahn mi
has slow braised pork.
And a nice blend of vegetables.
It's a burst of flavors
in your mouth.
What are we making?
-A braised pork belly bahn mi.
-Okay.
We have our pork belly rubbed
with some kosher salt,
black pepper,
and this is just ready
to go to the flat top.
Five minutes a side.
Soy sauce, rice wine vinegar,
fish sauce, and chili paste.
All right. In the oven.
Three hours. Good to go.
All right, sriracha aioli.
Let's see it.
Eggs, fresh garlic,
seasoned salt,
sherry vinegar,
and then canola oil.
-Hit it.
-And our chili paste.
Okay, now we're into the --
Pickling brine
for our daikon radish.
Just start with some water,
rice vinegar,
apple cider vinegar,
black cardamom seeds.
Didn't see that coming.
Whole black pepper, bay leaves,
coriander seeds, cumin,
onion powder, salt, and sugar.
Let this all dissolve
and steep a little bit.
Pour that over the ice.
And we just
start shaving daikon.
Oh, in chips, not in strips.
How long is this gonna to
take to pickle?
-Overnight.
-Build it, brother.
Start with the pork belly.
So it's a really nice gentle
medium-sized portion.
Definitely.
Hear about this health craze,
what's going on today?
You know what you're getting
when you're having
pork belly anyways.
He's still in firefighter mode.
He's still burning
those calories.
-A little sriracha aioli.
-A little?
Our pickled daikon,
fresh jalapeños,
Thai basil, fresh cilantro,
shredded carrots,
bean sprouts, and hoisin.
Give these guys
some of our braising liquid.
There we go. A family
is six can feed off of this.
♪♪
If you're a pork belly fan,
you'll love it.
The pork is super tender
like all of the fresh veggies
and the basil.
You need the acid
from the pickling.
-It is rich. Nicely done.
-Thank you.
And the pork belly bahn mi.
The pork belly is a guilty
pleasure for me.
-It's such a treat.
-The pork is really juicy.
It's got some crunchiness
to it also.
How do you describe this place?
What makes it so good?
All the meats are very tasty.
Big enough portions for you?
Huge portions. Perfect.
Mash going down.
He backs up the unique
side of it?
Yes, sir.
The spices and the flavors,
you can't get it
anywhere else in town.
Nana's meatloaf order up.
This meatloaf sandwich
is awesome.
He mixes in the mashed potatoes
and the little bit of everything
that you would eat
with a meatloaf.
I used to make it
with my grandmother.
Okay, so you have a meatloaf
background.
Yeah. People are afraid
of meatloaf.
A lot of people had to eat it
as a kid,
but typically it was overcooked,
under seasoned,
and had to be covered in copious
amounts of ketchup to ever work.
Yeah. So we're making
a meatloaf mix.
Yellow onions, red onion,
Anaheim peppers, some garlic,
red wine vinegar,
some worcestershire, a mix of
seasoned salt and kosher salt,
black pepper,
oregano, and thyme.
-Got it.
-So we'll give this a blend.
80/20 ground beef.
And what else?
-Pork sausage.
-Great.
Meatloaf mix.
I'll save about half of it.
Puréed tomatoes,
save about half of that.
Some eggs and panko.
Okay, load it up.
And it goes into the oven at 350
degrees for an hour and a half.
Bring it out. Let it cool.
We're gonna make
our meatloaf gravy now.
Okay.
-Meatloaf mix that we left over.
-Got it.
Puréed tomatoes.
Ketchup.
Tomato paste and mustard.
That's a combo
right there, folks.
Cook it for 45 minutes.
All right.
We've got
our cooled meatloaf
and these will go
just to the grill right here.
A little bit of oil down
and the mashed.
Add our meatloaf gravy,
some caramelized onions.
Now you're getting
all fancy dancey now.
-That's how we do it.
-The dancey or the fancy part?
-A little bit of both.
-Okay.
Provolone cheese, steam.
I don't understand where
all that's going.
On there?
Oh! That'll be fun to eat
once it cools down
to the temperature of the sun.
♪♪
The meatloaf is tender,
not dry at all.
Great with the provo
and good job
on the caramelized onions, too.
It definitely gives
a different textural piece.
It's really good bread.
It's really nice and light
and doesn't compete
with the sandwich.
Yeah.
And the mashed potato
is nice and silky.
You get the creamy side
of the mashed potato meatloaf
thing you want and then you get
the tender meatball,
tomato sauce, gravy type setup.
-Really good sandwich.
-Thank you.
I have the Nana's Meatloaf
for you.
It's tender and I love
the mashed potatoes on it.
And with the cheese
and the sauce,
it just makes
the perfect combination.
It blows mom's meatloaf
out of the water. Sorry, mom.
Reuben in the window.
It's just a great dining
experience for everybody.
The style of food
that you do here,
you dream it up, you'd think
about it and off we go.
Yep.
Overachiever.
Who's this fireman?
[ Laughs ]
Reno's lucky.
Good job, brother.
♪♪
That's it for this week.
But don't you worry,
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
How about yourself?
Where you from?
-I am from Boston.
-How long you been here?
12, 13 years.
Right here in this booth.
Got it, 12 or 13.
They're so friendly
at this restaurant.
Yes. [ Laughs ]