You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint,
you checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D', how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
Everyone knows I can't resist
scratch bait, savory cooking,
but these places
are serving sweets
I'd even sink my teeth into.
In Kansas City...
Just because you're vegan
doesn't mean
you don't want to eat
like a fat kid sometimes.
A little sugar and spice...
Them's a tomatillos.
...making brunch
twice as nice.
A burger joint
piling it high...
I have to stretch.
...shaking it up,
and taking over Texas.
BOSO: You're going
to blow us up.
Am I going to
blow them up or what?
Plus in Albuquerque...
This is what I like, getting
a chance to go on the open road,
make meatballs with mama.
...a secret steak house,
you got to know how to find.
Dishing out tradition...
Sometimes 6 is okay,
sometimes 12
for the guy
from the show.
...and cultural confections.
You enjoying that?
[ Record needle scratches ]
Yeah.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
OG "Triple D" joints are
constantly keeping me
in the loop about new places
popping up in their town.
Like back in 2013, when my buddy
Stretch from Grinders
took me to this funky
corner joint in Kansas City.
With their busted out brunch
with hardy helpings
and sweet satisfaction.
Pork hash.
This is Succotash.
Got a pot roast sandwich up.
It's the best place in town
for breakfast, brunch, lunch.
I got a modern Elvis.
Kind of glorified comfort food
with fantastic ingredients.
FIERI: Because this fireball
is behind the line.
Delicious.
Chef and owner Beth Barton,
whose unique flavors are only
upstaged by her unique past.
What did you do
before this?
Uh, I was a sex ed teacher.
[ Needle scratches ]
[ Whistling ]
What's up?
Her food is a lot like her.
Happy and lucky
and bursting with love.
[ Laughter ]
It's passionate.
Fantastic.
How's life of a --
It was what, six, seven
years ago, we saw you.
It was 2013.
When you came
to the restaurant,
I had moved
from the city market.
Right.
And so...
And just got done
tiling the walls yourself.
Yeah.
I put
all this up myself.
Wait, wait, wait. You tiled
the restaurant yourself.
I tiled it.
I did all the front.
I've always been
very hands on.
Basically built
the restaurant.
I did.
Short of hanging the hood?
Yeah.
What's been new
in the restaurant?
Busy, busy, busy.
I have the pork hash.
After we filmed,
it was pork hash,
pork hash, pork hash.
Well done, sister.
Well done.
We're going to make
pork hash.
Two of my favorite words.
It starts with a rub.
Black pepper,
dark chili powder,
paprika, salt,
a healthy dose to cayenne.
[ Whistles ]
And then this lovely
butt of pork...
But seriously.
Rub it in, kind of give it
a good spanking.
[ Whip cracks ]
A little mirepoix.
Saran and foil.
[ Whistles ]
For a girl that didn't go
to any culinary school,
you should know
the trade secrets.
In the oven.
What temp?
275.
15 hours.
Yeah.
Now.
I'm going to make
a tomatillo verde.
So we're going to take
the roasted tomatillo,
put them in my fantastic
brand-new food processor.
You want to do the honors,
or should I?
Your honor, Your Honor.
[ Whirring ]
Thems is tomatillos.
You remember
the food processor?
Mm-hmm.
-That's it?
-This, theoretically,
should lift off,
but it doesn't because
it's like everything else
in my kitchen.
So we're just going to lift
this up and pour it.
Oh, no, you didn't.
Oh, completely.
It's sad.
Give me a long set
of tongs, please.
This just turned into HGTV.
And to your credit, you took
a long time trying to fix that.
I remember.
Wap!
-Did you get it?
-No.
Still don't have one?
No, I still need one.
Remember, you were going
to send me one, but you know.
You didn't get it?
No.
I figured after six years
of "Triple D"
and everybody showing up
from around the country.
No, I bought one.
Okay.
I bought one right after
you left.
It was a valiant effort.
We add the red onion...
[ Whistles ]
...minced garlic,
salt, white pepper,
fresh cilantro.
A lot going on to just
the pork hash.
BARDEN:
Pork is out of the oven.
And it just goes into --
And it just shreds
that easy. Okay.
So potatoes are down.
Then you take a nice
generous dose of pork.
Holy hash, Batman.
Delicious verde.
Wow.
And that is the pork hash.
Mm.
That pork is just
really tender, great flavor.
It's not your average
breakfast hash.
Well done.
Killer hash.
Tell me about the menu.
What's new? Anything exciting?
I've been doing a lot more
vegan and vegetarian
and a lot of things
from scratch.
Give me some of
the highlights.
What are some
of the key dishes?
I'm doing something
called a Modern Elvis.
It's a vegan French toast,
organic almond butter,
caramelized bananas,
and vegan bacon.
Nice.
So we're going to start
with the vegan bacon.
Maple syrup, tamari,
a little smokey smoke,
neutral oil, spices.
So you have to have a base
for the bacon,
and we use a traditional
spring roll wrapper.
They idea is to get
a full coating on it,
and then we'll drop these down.
They'll start to edge up
like a bacon.
Now we're ready to make
the batter.
Flour, baking powder, sugar,
cinnamon, salt, non-milk milk,
little cider vinegar, vanilla,
and now we'll whisk together.
Dredge the bread in the batter
and cook it in vegan butter
on the grill.
Then I'm going to slice bananas
and caramelize those.
Now we'll plate
the French toast,
adding our almond butter
to the top, caramelized bananas.
And we'll finish with
our homemade vegan caramel.
Start with the vegan butter,
the brown sugar,
cashew cream,
the non-dairy milk.
Stir that in.
We'll add the rosemary to it.
And then quickly
whisk in the vanilla.
And then top it
with the vegan bacon crumble.
And here is our Modern Elvis.
Modern Elvis up!
WOMAN: You've got this, like,
cushy soft bread, caramelized
in sweet bananas,
and this caramel on it.
It's beautiful.
MAN: It's syrupy,
it's caramel-y, it's crunchy.
It's like every texture
in one bite. It's perfect.
Something you treat yourself to.
Just because you're vegan
doesn't mean
you don't want to eat
like a fat kid sometimes.
[ Laughs ] I'm sorry,
but, like, it's true.
It's the best line
in the world.
-I like it.
-You're a culinary
gangster girl.
-I like it.
You are really all that
and then some.
Please run for office.
I'd vote for you.
[ Laughs ]
You have the right ideas
and the right energy
and the right attitude.
Yeah, but you're already
the mayor of Flavor Town.
There's really
no room for me.
We need some senators.
[ Laughs ]
With sweet brunch options
like that, my guess is
she'd have everyone's
vote in town.
Now coming up...
Giving away the farm on
that one, old Quince.
...a burger joint
with a twist...
That's a championship
burger right there.
...and a treat is now
a "Triple D" deluxe in Dallas.
Tell me what happened.
BOSO: We have
17 restaurants.
I'm so happy for you guys.
Back in 2009, we discovered
this Dallas burger joint
whose creative combos
were out of bounds.
These days, they're still
stacking up
plus stirring in some
serious sweetness.
This is Twisted Root
Burger Company.
Got your fresh for 15.
Twisted Root is literally
my favorite burger place.
Vegabond.
This is what Dallas is all
about. This is Texas, baby.
I saw Twisted Root on
"Triple D" about 10 years ago,
and it made me want to come
up here and have a burger.
FIERI: That's thanks to
Quincy Hart and Jason Boso,
two patty flipping friends
who shared a vision.
How did you come up with
Twisted Root Burger Company?
We met in culinary school
our first day.
All through school,
we talked about restaurants.
Three hams and a chili.
We always complained about
a quality burger in Dallas.
We said, "Let's get
this together and do this,"
and here we are.
It's like
a Disney movie.
A tear coming.
[ Laughs ]
Is this the foundation
of the Twisted Root Burger?
This is it.
It's a mixture
of 81, 19 and 73, 27.
So Guy pulls out
a piece of paper
and starts doing
the little math.
We're getting
ourselves a 77, 23.
There you go.
He got it right.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
FIERI: And what's the average
size burger here?
I make sure
they're eight ounces.
Okay. So do you measure
them out at a time?
I can pretty much
eyeball it.
I'm going to be
the inspector here today.
Well, giving away the farm
on that one, old Quince.
What'd I do, Guy?
8.4. I'm in.
Here we go.
Can it be, folks?
Eight!
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
Not that I have a competition
about food or anything.
No, chefs don't do that.
Now let's press one out.
You used to do this,
too, huh, Guy?
Uh-huh, I used to get in trouble
in the kitchen, also.
Give me a Western, brother.
A little pepper jack cheese
on that, some bacon.
Look at that.
Get after them.
Come here, bacon.
Some onion strings on that.
Build a little nest
for those jalapeños.
FIERI: There you go.
Mmm. [ Whistles ]
That's like the everlasting
burgers stopper right there.
900 flavors.
Spicy, sweet, crunchy, salty.
That's a championship
burger right there.
That's a burger done right.
FIERI: But the Wagyu burger
is giving the old winners
a run for their money.
We've got your Le Wagyu.
Wagyu is just
a really fatty cow.
And of course
that's the delicious part.
We're going to make some
thyme onions for Le Wagyu.
Pour these devils down there.
Just want to make sure that all
of the onions are caramelized.
Next step, add some fresh thyme.
Sprinkle some of that on there.
There you go.
Okay, so we're going to actually
make the patty.
We make our patties
eight ounces.
Hopefully I do better
than I did last time.
Drum roll.
[ Drum roll ]
8.3.
I'm not very good.
[ Laughs ]
We'll put it on the press.
We're going to put this
on the grill.
Some Dijon mustard.
And now we'll turn that over.
Our intention is to get
a crust on the burger.
I'm going to add
some thyme onions.
Gruyère cheese.
I'm going to put
a bell cover over it.
Spray some water,
and it causes a steam,
and it melts the cheese.
Voilà.
We're going to put
this bad boy on the bun.
Hand cut fries.
There you have it.
The Le Wagyu.
MAN: I absolutely love
the Wagyu burger.
It's a juicy, the cheese
is amazingly melted on it.
It's cooked perfectly.
Because of the Dijon mustard
crusted over the top,
the caramelized onions
on top of that makes it juicy
as well as the Wagyu beef,
which is the top beef
you can get.
What's the future? What's going
to happen here to Twisted Root?
Is there going to be
Twisted Root 2, a spinoff?
Well, we hope
you're going to blow us up
and we're going twisted
in a lot
of different
directions, we hope.
Am I going to blow
them up or what?
[ Explosion ]
FIERI: And coming up,
it's not all about
the out of bounds burgers.
Boom, she done.
She is done.
Because their shakes
are taking them over the top.
MAN: You give me a shake
that has bacon in it,
I'm a happy man for life.
FIERI: And these dudes are
the gift that keeps on giving.
Round of beers on me!
[ Cheers and applause ]
FIERI:
Back in 2009 in Dallas, Texas,
we dug up a pretty funky find,
the Twisted Root Burger Company.
It was so up "Triple D"'s alley
that in 2011,
I cruised by again
for a little check in.
It's not every day that you give
somebody the golden goose
and then they go and make
seven more golden gooses.
Is it golden gooses
or geeses?
I think
it's geeses now.
[ Laughs ] How long ago were
we here doing "Triple D"?
Two years ago
you were here.
Two years ago, you come
and shoot the show.
Tell me what happened.
We tripled our business
the next day after
we aired with you.
We had to shut the door
because we ran out of food.
How many Twisted Root
do you have?
We're up to seven.
And eight years
after that...
We went from 24 employees
to 524 employees right now,
and 17 restaurants.
Since the show aired,
it's been obviously
a bunch of different
locations,
but more importantly,
the classic menu
that started the restaurant
is still here.
So the chipotle guacamole
grilled onion burger,
is that what it was?
Chipotle guacamole,
fried onion.
Come on. You can say
it five times fast.
Chipotle guacamole,
fried onion burger.
Yeah!
Chipotle guacamole,
fried onion burger.
Boom, she done.
She is done.
She's done. We need to put
a little cheddar it.
Cheddar make her better?
Cheddar make it better.
[ Sizzling ]
Okay, here we go, Guy.
A little chipotle sauce.
FIERI: Oh, boy. You meant like
seriously chipotle sauce.
Right. Some guacamole
and some onion strings.
No, of course,
I have to stretch.
[ Laughter ]
You have a bib?
Like a drop cloth.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
Look at that bite,
like a piranha.
That's got great
chipotle flavor.
I like the guacamole
in there,
cooked medium rare,
perfectly.
Another quality burger.
A little twisted,
but quality.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: And if you think those
burgers are crazy, take a look
at what people
are washing them down with.
So we do
a thick custard shake.
And we kept trying to up
the game on that.
FIERI: Yep. By adding
outrageous ingredients
like toasted
marshmallow s'mores,
lemon ice box pie,
and this crazy concoction.
Got a Fat Elvis shake.
We're making the peanut butter
banana sandwich.
This is going to be
an accoutrement
to our Fat Elvis.
Texas toast,
peanut butter, a banana.
Let that grill a little bit.
We're going to dust that
with a little cinnamon sugar.
Now this goes up
to the shake making station.
First step's the custard.
Chocolate sauce,
peanut butter sauce,
unsalted peanuts,
and a bunch of pieces of bacon.
Just giving that salty sweet
to this shake,
which Elvis was
pretty famous for.
Banana pieces.
Give that another good spin.
You're going to garnish that
with that sandwich we made.
Whipped cream on top
and bacon peanut crumble.
Get after it.
MAN: The chocolate,
the peanut butter,
you give me a shake
that has bacon in it,
you can give me
nothing else in the world,
I'm happy,
I'm a happy man for life.
You know, it's both sweet
and savory at the same time,
and it just strikes
a really good balance
between both of them.
Give it up for your owner, man.
This guy did great.
[ Cheers and applause ]
I always wanted to say this,
round of beers on me!
[ Cheers and applause ]
And actually,
it didn't stop there.
I ended up with
two or three rounds,
and I might have had four
or five rounds,
and we had a good old time.
Hook 'em up.
17 locations?
Brother, I'll drink to that.
Now coming up
in Albuquerque...
I could
be standing in 1972
and not even
know a difference.
...an old school steak house
serving up
savory specialties
and Greek sweets...
This is a money meatball.
...and hiding in plain sight.
A liquor store, restaurant,
steakhouse, in New Mexico
with a dude named Screwy Louie.
[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: Now you know what
I always say on "Triple D."
If it's funky, I'll find it.
You want to talk about funky?
I found this place
in Albuquerque, New Mexico,
back in 2008.
And I'll tell you what,
it's the real deal.
You want a good dinner?
Hit the liquor store,
where you'll find
a great steakhouse?
Oh, behind the beer cooler,
I guess.
It's still cooking up Greek
classics from behind the brew.
This is Monte Carlo
Liquor & Steak House.
I saw Monte Carlo on "Triple D."
It's just a fun place to come,
and the food is fantastic.
The baklava.
I've been coming here
for about 30 years.
You don't find this kind
of atmosphere anywhere else.
You can tell they've been
around for a long time.
I could be standing in 1972
and not even know a difference.
-Exactly.
-That's what it feels like.
It's pretty retro,
isn't it?
FIERI: Which is fitting since
Angelina and Mike Katsaros
opened this place
in the early '70s.
And once Mike passed away,
his kids stepped in
to help their mom.
[ Laughter ]
This is a big family.
We grew up in this place.
We love this place.
And everybody's a part of it.
Including their eldest son,
Lou, a.k.a...
Screwy Louie.
[ Laughs ]
It stuck, and that's it.
FIERI: And there's sticking to
Mama's tried and true recipes.
What do you got?
We have some
Greek chicken right now.
Did you eat this at home
when you were a kid?
You bet. Whatever Mama
has in the oven,
that's what you're eating,
no matter what it is.
No, I dig it.
Little garlic, salt,
pepper, oregano.
Oregano.
Then we just flip it over.
Do the same.
Hey, you do pretty good.
Well, you know what?
You've done this before?
Yeah.
Just a little
olive oil on top.
Little drizzle on top.
There you go.
Just put a little bit
of butter inside there.
Should put some in
for you, too.
[ Chuckles ]
Is our bird done?
Well, let's take a look.
Wow. Look at how
juicy that is.
We're going to put
a little bit
of juice on
that thing for you.
Oy!
Oh, it got
all over my shirt!
I know why they call him
Screwy Louie.
Sorry about that.
Oh!
A year and a half of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives",
how is it that
I'm at a liquor store,
restaurant, steak house in
New Mexico with a dude named...
Screwy Louie.
Screwy Louie,
and I get greased?
Mm, that's great.
There you go.
Mm, dude.
You enjoying that?
Yeah.
Guy loved it.
He said he's never tasted Greek
chicken seasoned that way,
which is I'm sure, like I said,
it's my mom's recipe, so...
It's easy to be the hero
when you got your mom here.
Thanks, Mom.
But that's not the only trick
she had up her sleeve.
Let's make meatballs.
-Onion.
-Some white onion.
Garlic,
oregano, pepper.
A little black pepper.
Salt.
What is this?
Greek mint.
Really, seriously.
I've made some meatballs.
I don't know that I've made
with any Greek mint.
Eggs.
So you guys will make this
ahead of time.
Let it marinate.
Roll them nice and light.
Now, Mama, how many meatballs
do you get with an order?
Three.
Sometimes six is okay?
No, no.
Sometimes 12 for the guy
from the show.
Sometimes all of them.
He got along real well
with my mother.
This is what I like,
getting a chance to go
on the open road,
make meatballs with Mama.
Take a look at that.
Wow. Mmm.
All that Greek mint in there.
This is a money meatball.
[ Laughs ]
KATSAROS: My mother passed away
10 years ago.
We miss her immensely.
We were with her
every single day.
FIERI: And they still are
because her memory is alive
in every dish they make.
Like your sweet tooth
satisfying baklava.
My mother had this
recipe forever.
This is going to be
the filling -- crushed walnuts,
cinnamon, sugar, mixing it up.
We're going to start now
with 10 sheets of phyllo dough,
and we have to put butter
between each one.
Every layer is going
to get buttered.
Now we're ready
for the filler.
Next layer, we're going
to put another
three pieces of
phyllo dough on it.
Put a whole handful
in this one here.
Now to finish it off,
we're going to put
10 more layers of phyllo.
We're all ready to bake it now
in a 350 degree oven
for about 45 minutes.
Now that the baklava is done,
we're going to top it
with a finishing sauce,
which is water,
New Mexico honey, sugar,
Mandarin orange, vanilla,
and a stick of cinnamon.
Over the top,
take a little while to soak in.
Now it's ready to be cut.
This is Mama's baklava.
It's crispy. It's sweet.
You can't ask for better.
It's crunchy.
It has a great honey flavor.
The love and care that they
put into it is incredible.
-Anything going to change?
-No, no.
-Nah.
-You know what,
if you remodeled,
I think the flavor would
come out of the air.
We'll never remodel. It's going
to stay '70s forever here.
Do jazz hands for me.
Jazz hands.
[ Laughs ]
Why change when what they're
doing is working so well?
And who knew that the nation had
such a sweet tooth?
Like at
the Monte Carlo Steakhouse,
where they're still
delivering Mama's
Greek goodness in Albuquerque.
And at Succotash in Kansas City,
where Beth's out of the box
brunch is bringing
down the house.
Thank you.
Well done.
And in Dallas, where the boys
from Twisted Root
are growing like gangbusters
with they're not so basic
burgers and money milkshakes.
Plus, we'll indulge in more
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
next time on "Triple D Nation."
Nugget, log, loaf,
chunk, plump, and juicy.
Nice.
All favorite words.
Sounds like all my
roommates in college.
Bah, dah, bum.
Seriously.
And we'll be right back
after this.