You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning,
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
[ Engine revs ]
Like on this trip...
Outrageous.
...Filipino food
at its finest...
Top, top items we ever
had in "Triple D."
...now rolling all over Oahu.
Hey!
[ Horn honks ]
And I can't shove it
in my face fast enough.
As soon as I do this,
nine buttons
are gonna
break off this shirt.
In San Diego...
Next, on "The Dumbest Things
Done on TV"...
...a tortilla factory
turned taqueria...
How do I approach it?
...making unforgettable
taquitos.
Tell the folks at home
something interesting
as I scarf down my third.
Plus, in Kansas City...
Booyah you.
I've got my hands full
with this one.
Did she just say,
"I'm gonna booyah you"?
But the Asian-inspired eats
are out-of-bounds.
These are awesome.
Nailed it!
[ Laughs ]
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
You know, on
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives,"
I think that I have
probably tried
every ethnicity of food
or close to it,
and I don't think
it's any surprise for folks
that Asian-inspired food
is my fave,
and one of those
is Filipino food,
so I'm here
on the island of Oahu,
and I found out that one of
my favorite Filipino restaurants
has got a food truck.
I got to check it out.
This is Elena's.
Hi, guys.
You get great service
and great food. Can't top that.
The menu here is fantastic,
and they're not just in Waipahu,
but you can see their food truck
all over the place.
We're very proud
that "Triple D" came here
because then we felt like,
"Yep. We know
what we're talking about."
FIERI: So does my buddy Reno
from Fresh Catch.
You got to remember him.
Aaaaah!
He's the one that took me here
back in 2014.
Why this place?
This place feels like home,
bruh. It's a family operation.
The cook's a little bit
of crazy in the back.
[ Laughter ]
That would be Richard Butuyan,
who runs this place
with his sister, Mellissa,
cooking their mom Elena's
recipes from the Philippines.
Gisantes is ready.
How do you describe
Filipino food?
[ Chuckles ]
Can I ask my sister?
Yeah, why don't we
ask your sister,
the one with the brains?
It's a mixture of Spanish
and Chinese.
Wow.
That's what it is.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
What's up, brother?
How long ago was it
I saw you guys?
Five years ago.
We show up --
tiny, little place,
strip mall,
and you blew my mind.
Mmm.
That dish --
what was the dish we had?
Lechon special.
Still to this day,
of the top, top,
top items we ever had
in "Triple D."
♪♪
RICHARD: So, we start
with the pork belly.
FIERI: We're gonna cut
all this into cubes?
Yeah.
Skin on and everything?
Skin on.
Okay, so these aren't cubes.
Those are chunks.
Chunks, yeah.
Does your mom know that
you're screwing her recipes up?
Yeah. I hope so.
I hope not.
You hope so,
you hope not.
I was nervous at first.
I can't get a straight answer
out of you.
He was so scared.
You doing all right?
Not really.
You're doing a great job.
Gonna boil it first.
Boil it away.
So, where are we now?
We're gonna make
some pork adobo fried rice.
Pork adobo.
Yeah.
Oil and rice.
Fry it up.
Soy sauce.
Shoyu or soy sauce?
Shoyu sauce.
Soy sauce.
[ Chuckling ]
Shoyu sauce.
Shoyu. We'll just go
with shoyu. Shoyu.
[ Both laugh ]
Oyster sauce and then
some black pepper.
Garlic powder.
Mix it up a little.
Now we're gonna add
some pork adobo.
And what does
the adobo mean?
Vinegary.
Mix it up.
Now we're done with this?
We're done with this.
Great.
Pork belly.
Now we're gonna
deep-fry this?
Yes.
♪♪
Chop it up.
[ Crunch ]
That's crazy.
Like chicharrón and a rib
and bacon at the same time.
Now we're gonna add
the chopped tomatoes,
chopped onions,
fish sauce,
Hawaiian sea salt,
green onions.
Put this on here?
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, then I'll let you
put it on.
As soon as I do this,
nine buttons are gonna
break off this shirt.
That's awesome.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm. Crunchy pork --
the skin, the fat,
the tender meat.
You put that
fresh tomato in there...
You got a party
in your mouth.
[ Laughs ]
That's right.
Stay over there.
I've made it at home
a few times, and it's good,
but there's something
about the way you guys make it
that just crushes.
You make the food
at the restaurant,
you put it
in the food truck,
you take it out,
and you go sell it.
MELLISSA:
We have two food trucks
because we have people
coming from all over the world.
What are the heavy hitters?
What's everybody asking for?
The lechon special.
This is the second
popular dish.
What's this?
Sari sari.
Uh-huh.
MELLISSA: "Sari sari"
in Filipino means "variety,"
so we make
a sari sari vegetable soup.
I'm gonna start
the pork broth.
We use water, fish sauce,
Hawaiian salt,
tomatoes and the onions,
the eggplant, long squash,
ong choy, pork.
Then I'll put it on the fire
for 10 minutes.
So, next step is shrimp.
Put some oil in our saucepan,
tomatoes and onions,
granulated garlic,
Hawaiian salt.
Now I'm gonna add the shrimp.
[ Sizzling ]
Now I'm gonna plate the dish,
putting it in a deep bowl,
with the shrimp
to top off the sari sari.
That's the lechon.
I know it's the lechon.
That's what I'm digging
around for.
He loved the lechon so much
that we decided to put it
into our sari sari.
This is, like,
what all the locals eat.
This is delicious.
I mean,
any time you can get
the fried pork in there
with this nice broth...
Mmm.
That is fantastic.
It's a healthy dish.
More of a --
More like a comfort food.
Comfort food with just a
little bit of fried pork in it.
Don't let that
bother you.
When it hits your lips,
it's like "Boom."
You taste the eggplant,
then you go into the squash.
Then the moistness of the pork
is unbelievable.
It's the best parts
of seafood and pork.
[ Laughs ]
Give me the update.
What's been going on?
Crazy. Just crazy.
How crazy?
Tell me the level
of crazy.
Crazy like we're running with
chickens without their heads.
Just crazy.
Crazy.
Crazier than the way
you just explained it.
We took over the space
next to us.
We had nine tables.
Now we have 15 tables.
More room to run around.
Remember how tight it was
before?
I do remember
how tight it was. Yeah.
We're all like this,
"Oh, my God."
And after you eat
that much lechon...
You know...
I got to go.
I'm sorry.
...we couldn't
get out of there.
We were shoehorned in.
FIERI: And coming up...
Your mom's
out-of-bounds, bro.
...Elena's is providing
to be a power hitter...
How many of these
do you make -=
About 1,000 a week.
No!
...with a whole lineup
of out-of-the-park
Filipino flavors.
I love it, you guys.
♪♪
Here's your order.
Thank you.
FIERI: I'm on the island
of Oahu, checking in
on all-star siblings
Richard and Mellissa...
It's so good.
...who I first met in 2014,
when I hit up their tiny joint,
Elena's Filipino Food.
Where's Filipino food
been all my life?
FIERI:
Now what are we making?
Fried pork.
So, we're just gonna
slice it thin?
So, this is
a boneless pork butt?
Boneless pork butt.
We're gonna make
the marinade.
Raw onions,
bay leaves,
fresh garlic.
Mom's recipe again?
Yeah. Everything's
Mom's recipe here.
Garlic powder,
some black pepper,
Hawaiian sea salt.
Apple cider vinegar?
Put in the pork.
How long we gonna
marinate the pork?
We marinate it
for about a day.
♪♪
We're gonna make
a pickled ong choy...
Pickled ong choy?
...for our side dish
for the fried pork,
so we're gonna make
the marinade.
Okay.
Start off with onions,
some fresh garlic,
garlic powder,
some black pepper,
Hawaiian chili pepper,
and then
some Hawaiian salt.
And then we're gonna
finish it off with some vinegar.
♪♪
We put the cut ong choy
in the marinade.
This marinates
for a few days.
And that goes with
the fried pork?
Yes. I cook it
in the skillet.
Cut it up
while it's hot.
♪♪
Look at this, dude.
Good?
Outrageous.
It's a little bit of vinegar,
a little bit of heat,
little bit of crunch,
little veggie piece to it.
Your mom's
out-of-bounds, bro.
[ Laughs ]
Elena.
What did you make here?
What are these?
This is a Shanghai lumpia.
Shanghai lumpia.
We have our ground pork,
and we're gonna add
our minced shiitake mushrooms,
minced water chestnuts,
our onions,
granulated garlic,
ground black pepper,
eggs,
and shoyu.
We're gonna mix this together
and add our Hawaiian salt.
Here are our egg roll wrappers.
We're gonna fill up our
piping bag and pipe out the mix.
So, next step is
we're gonna roll them,
and you go into your egg wash
so there's a seal.
And we put it into the fryer.
And this is
our vinegar garlic sauce.
We're gonna start off
with our brown vinegar,
granulated garlic,
ground black pepper,
and our Hawaiian salt.
And now we're ready
to plate our lumpia.
♪♪
How many of these
do you make --
About 1,000 a week.
No!
Crazy. Yes.
That filling is tender.
RICHARD: Mm-hmm.
The exterior is nice
and crunchy, but it's light.
That's my hands.
[ Laughs ]
MAN: It's crispy.
With the dipping sauce,
it makes the flavor pop out.
WOMAN:
It's crunchy and lovely.
And I needed more of it.
[ Laughs ]
I know why Reno said
come check it out.
It's the real deal, man.
Thanks for letting us
be part of that family.
You are part of the family --
part of the team.
We're part of
the "Triple D" ohana.
[ Laughter ]
Watch out
for these two.
[ Laughter ]
Man, if only Route 66
stretched all the way to Hawaii
so we could that food truck
rolling on the mainland.
Now, up next,
a spot in San Diego...
Man, they're good.
...cranking out
scratch-made tortillas...
Four, five...
Aaah!
...and taquitos
by the ton.
Who wants
another taquito?
[ Indistinct shouting ]
♪♪
FIERI: Nothing makes
a Mexican joint more real-deal
than authentic
house-made tortillas,
so when I found
this joint back in 2007,
I knew it was gonna be legit.
Mexican places may be
a dime a dozen in San Diego,
but this one, well,
it's old-school and pure gold.
This is El Indio.
Green chile verde!
It was so fun to see
that Guy had eaten here.
We can see why he likes it.
Always comforting, always fresh.
I love the fresh corn tortillas,
and they make the best here.
FIERI:
That's because Ralph Pesqueira
and his daughter, Jennifer,
are cranking out tortillas
the same way his parents did
when they opened
the place in 1940.
We started making tortillas
by hand,
and then a group
of my dad's friends decided
that they would make
a tortilla machine,
and the first
little machine was built.
FIERI:
Let's play checkers.
My dad was teaching him
how to make corn tortillas
the old-fashioned way.
Now we turn?
That's it.
Water comes on.
We want to light it off.
Get the heat
started to it.
I like the flip-flop
and the hot water.
I know.
He's wearing sandals
with bare feet and...
[ Laughs ]
Aaah! Gee!
I'm sorry. [ Laughs ]
[ Laughs mockingly ]
Gets washed,
gets dumped in.
Inside that grinder
is this.
If you want to
reach up there,
you can actually feel
the stone in there.
Next, on "The Dumbest Things
Done on TV"...
[ Drumroll ]
Aa-aa-aa-aah!
[ Beep ]
Oh, yeah,
I felt it.
[ Laughs ]
Just drop it.
That's it.
The tortilla comes off.
Any idea how they puff up?
Hot air?
We got a little man
in there that...
Ha ha ha!
Stack them 12 in a stack.
Four, five...
Aaah!
Two...
Fan...tastic.
FIERI: And those tortillas
are used for everything --
tacos, quesadillas,
and, of course, the taquito.
So, we take a little bit
of the mixture.
That is shredded
roast beef.
Over and pull back.
Now roll it tight.
Now your toothpick,
you're gonna put in
approximately
one inch down.
Pick up your taquitos.
So, we don't want to them
to be super crunchy, crispy,
where they fall apart.
No.
Now what you want to do
is you want
to take your fingers
and crack it open
and roll it like that
towards you just a little bit.
So I want you to lay your sauce
in it like that.
A scoop of guacamole
in each one of them,
The cheese, lettuce,
and that's it.
How do I approach it?
In?
Any way you want.
On?
Mmm.
Man, they're good.
This should just be called
"Home of the great taquito."
And the name still fits,
especially with their new
potato taquito on the menu.
It's a vegetarian dish.
We make our potato
filling first,
and that is boiled potatoes,
butter,
vegetable broth,
white pepper,
and green onions.
We put them in a tortilla
and we roll them up.
[ Sizzling ]
♪♪
One order
of potato taquitos ready!
MAN: Crunchy on the outside,
a little soft on the inside.
The flavor is perfect.
WOMAN: You get this
lovely crunch of the lettuce,
the fresh tortillas are awesome,
and the potatoes
are really creamy.
Why don't you go ahead
and just
tell the folks at home
something interesting
as I scarf down
my third taquito.
Most people usually
only have a couple.
[ Laughs ]
After the show aired,
the customers came in droves.
FIERI:
And so did the new dishes,
like pork salsa verde.
PESQUEIRA: To cook our pork,
we boil it in water,
and then we brown it
in a pot and sear it.
And then we add our salsa verde.
It has green tomatoes,
jalapeños, onion,
fresh garlic.
[ Blender whirs ]
We season it with the bay leaf
and the salt and pepper.
It's served on a plate with rice
and beans and tortillas,
so you can make your own little
burrito or own little taco.
The meat is
extraordinarily tender,
and the sauce is just
the right amount of heat.
MAN: I love the pork
chili verde sauce,
how they mix it, and they have
all the sides and the beans.
It's just amazing.
♪♪
[ Richard laughs ]
[ Both laugh ]
RICHARD: We were so glad
that he came.
Here, we got
this little, tiny shop,
and he just made it
a great place to be.
Oh, dude.
Ow!
Who wants
another taquito?
[ Indistinct shouting ]
In my world, you can never
have enough taquitos,
and with that crowd,
I think they just proved it.
Now, coming up in Kansas City,
another dish I want
to dive right into...
For scientific purposes,
I'm gonna have eight more.
...made by a chef
we can never forget.
Winner, winner,
chili pepper wonton for dinner.
Yeah!
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: So, when you think
of Kansas City eats,
you probably go straight
to, like,
barbecue and burgers, right?
But, you know, I like to think
a little outside the box,
so when I was there in 2013,
I found a family-run joint
rockin' it with their
Taiwanese-Chinese combos.
Nowadays, they're more slammed
than ever,
and even though they lost
someone very special,
she'll always be a part
of the "Triple D" family.
This is Blue Koi.
♪♪
Shrimp with asparagus
and noodles.
The food is always
perfectly cooked.
Pork dumplings.
WOMAN: When you see the poster
for "Triple D,"
you know that it's gonna be
something good behind that door.
Jane and her family,
they're just super friendly
and welcoming to everybody.
FIERI: He means Jane Chang
and her brother Scott,
who run their original
location in KC
and their spot nearby
in Leawood, Kansas.
But when I was there in 2013,
it was their sister Mindy
who left the biggest impression.
Gonna booyah you.
[ Laughter ]
Did she just say,
"I'm gonna booyah you"?
[ Laughter ]
Sadly, Mindy passed away
in 2015,
but I'll always remember
how she poured her personality
into every dish.
Right now, we're gonna make
chili pepper wonton. It's bomb.
It's bomb?
It's bomb.
I need soy sauce,
vinegar,
sesame oil,
white pepper,
sugar, garlic.
Garlic?
Yes.
Cilantro.
Green onion
and a homemade hot oil.
We'll just stir.
Fantastic.
Yes.
[ Whistles ]
[ Spoons clatters ]
Oh! [ Laughs ]
Next?
Next, we're gonna make
chili pepper wonton filling.
Okay.
Okay?
Ground pork.
Ground pork,
ground chicken,
and chopped shrimp.
I like it.
A little bit of soy sauce,
rice wine,
sesame oil,
white pepper,
green onion.
We'll just mix
it really well.
Okay. And we're gonna
put this in wonton skins?
Yes.
And then put a bit
of it on the side here.
And just fold it.
Ooh-hoo!
And then we're gonna
fry them, boil them?
What do we do?
I like pan-fry them better.
Me too.
We think alike.
Well,
we got the same hair.
I know. Exactly.
Yeah.
But mine is natural.
You --
[ Laughs ]
Here you go.
♪♪
Mmm.
These are awesome.
Just for scientific purposes,
I'm gonna have...
eight more.
♪♪
Mmm.
Winner, winner, chili pepper
wonton for dinner at Blue Koi.
Yeah!
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: What a character,
and Mindy's energetic spirit
is still a big part
of this place.
Every day, we have Mindy with us
because the whole menu,
we have her items.
FIERI: Like her
Almond Asparagus Shrimp.
I sauté shrimp with garlic
and water,
mayonnaise, asparagus
and sun-dried tomato,
sugar.
Let them cook a little bit.
I'm going to cook the noodles
right now --
about three minutes.
This is a ginger-onion oil
soy sauce.
Now we're ready to plate.
Get a nice toss
for all the noodles.
Last, we sprinkle the almond,
and the dish is completed.
Your almond shrimp asparagus.
It's just my favorite sauce.
It's really light.
The asparagus is really crunchy,
and the noodles
are unbelievable.
The shrimp is snappy.
The flavors are just amazing.
Who's a better cook,
you or your sister?
Of course my sister.
She's right over there.
This is Jane,
and I cooked with Mindy.
Jane's Mindy's sister.
They share the same birthday,
but different year.
Did I get that right?
That's correct.
I'm so confused.
[ Laughs ]
JANE: I make
the fire bird chicken.
I'm the spicy one.
Fire bird chicken?
Right.
Sliced chicken breast.
Water.
We add some cornstarch
into it.
♪ Massage,
massage, massage ♪
Is that a massage song
you're singing?
Yeah, yeah.
Ginger-onion oil
we make in-house.
Got it.
♪♪
Brown it both sides?
Brown it both sides.
You put the garlic,
the rice wine.
Here comes fire!
And we have the sugar,
soy sauce,
Chinese barbecue sauce.
Now is the red pepper,
a little bit of
chicken broth into it,
a little bit of bamboo shoot
in there,
also green onions.
I like it.
Please enjoy.
♪ Too hot, too hot ♪
[ Man laughs ]
Another song.
Mmm. There's some heat --
no question.
Not typical Chinese food.
You got to come try it.
After the filming ended,
new people would come by.
JANE: People come in
and hug me,
and I don't even know
who they are.
That's incredible.
FIERI:
There may be new faces,
but their menu is still full
of old favorites,
like their pan-seared
pork dumplings.
To make our
pork dumpling filling,
we put fresh-ground pork,
salt, white pepper,
green onions,
and the sesame oil.
Mix, mix, mix.
Now we're ready to make
our pork dumpling.
♪♪
[ Sizzling ]
Let them steam and cook
till water dry.
And that's ready to eat.
Pan-fried pork dumpling!
MAN: They're perfectly cooked
on the outside.
The pork is perfect
in the middle. They're awesome.
Nice and tender,
they're pan-fried.
Very tasty.
Nice job.
It was so much fun.
I was proud to see Guy
with Jane, with Mindy.
She'll be saying,
"Nailed it!"
Nailed it!
[ Laughter ]
They sure are nailing it.
And it's nice to see
Mindy's legacy living on
through her righteous recipes.
Just like the legacy at Elena's,
where Mellissa and Richard
are trucking their mom's menu
all over Hawaii,
and at El Indio, where Jennifer
and her dad, Ralph,
are treating folks
to tortillas and taquitos,
just like his dad did.
And we'll hit up more
"Triple D" traditions
next time on "Triple D Nation."
You married?
Yeah. That my husband
over there.
You deal with this
every day?
[ Laughs ]
My trophy husband.
♪♪