Everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
lookin' for America's greatest
Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives.
This trip it's --
Da-da-duh!
It's real-deal
Southern cookin' --
Pour it all in there.
Don't hold back.
Served up in northern territory.
Get on the train
to Flavor Town, baby.
Like a Nashville Cajun combo
in Massachusetts --
Lights out.
Serious smoke in Nevada --
That's killer.
And up in Alaska --
What?
Don't judge.
A funky
barbecue fusion.
I'm in a happy spot right now,
so I'm just rambling.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here in Juneau, Alaska,
about five minutes
from the airport
to check out a joint
that's been a house.
It's also been a coffee shop.
So what does it turn
into next? Exactly:
A Southern smokehouse with kind
of an Asian bistro attitude.
Ah, you hear it every day.
This is Zerelda's Bistro.
Pork belly, table 6.
Pound for pound,
best in town, man.
Absolutely delicious.
I've got the shrimp noodle bowl.
How do you describe
this food here?
Asian fusion with comfort food.
The best thing here is Abby.
She's just full of joy,
and that comes in her food.
Everybody who knows
Abby, raise your hand.
Okay. That's no surprise
since Abby LaForce
has spent her life in this town.
But when she met Southern boy
Jeremy Barnett
and married
his barbecue background
with her Asian recipes,
a funky fusion
love affair was born.
We met online.
I was just posting pictures
of my tater tots,
and he was posting pictures
of his barbecue sandwiches.
I came to see her first.
I stayed a month.
I didn't have a return ticket.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
And the name
comes from what?
My grandma Zerelda.
She is from Texas.
My mother's Filipino,
my father's Caucasian.
This is gonna be
some kind of story
with a Filipino-
Caucasian-Asian-Southern
influence brisket pho bowl.
Brisket pho's ready.
There is nowhere else in Juneau
that does pho
quite like Zerelda's.
WOMAN: It's got the smoked
brisket in it,
so you get those
fusion of flavors,
and it's just to die for.
FIERI:
Okay. What are we makin'?
Smoked brisket pho.
You had me at hello on that.
Kosher salt.
Course black pepper.
Course.
Granulated garlic.
Chili.
This is Jeremy's recipe.
Jeremy's recipe, okay.
Actually.
Now that you two
are together as a couple,
you'll share these recipes.
Yeah. Yeah.
Brisket goes on for how long?
Ten to 12 hours at 225 degrees.
What kind of wood
are we smoking this with?
Apple and hickory.
So this is going to be
the beginning of our pho broth?
Yes. So we have cloves.
Fructus Amomi.
A-what?
It's the weirdest name.
It tastes like licorice.
Star anise.
Fennel seed.
Cinnamon stick.
Coriander seed.
So toast all the spices?
Yeah. We're going to take
roasted beef bones, raw chicken.
Water?
Yeah.
Carrot and a onion.
Green onion.
Ginger.
Garlic cloves.
Lots of chicken base.
And a little beef base.
Yeah. And then salt and pepper.
And then our spices?
Yeah.
So, this simmers
for three hours.
Beautiful looking brisket.
Oh, thank you.
Jeremy does a good job.
That is delicious.
So for we're -- we're going
in the right direction.
Okay. Okay, good.
This is the boiling liquid.
Keep going, everybody's
watching right now.
You eat some more brisket.
You like fish sauce?
I love fish sauce.
Good, good, good.
Have all of these drippings.
From the brisket,
from the smoker.
So right onto the noodles.
The brisket.
White onion, green onions,
and roasted sesame oil.
And then my garnish
if I want it.
♪♪
That is not
lacking in flavor.
That little smoke
kick is killer.
You got a big,
rich piece of meat.
Great vegetables
inside of it.
The kiss of the drippings
from the smoker makes it.
I like that the noodles
are steeping in the pho broth.
I don't like
soggy noodles.
I wouldn't want that
as my gang name, Soggy Noodles.
Who do you run with?
Stale Bread.
Flavor turf wars.
I'm in a happy spot right now,
so I'm just rambling.
This is, without question,
one of the most unique phos
I've had.
I can't get it
in my face fast enough.
Here is your pho.
I love the rich, rich broth
and also the smokiness
that comes with it.
It's just...
Mwah.
WOMAN:
It has all kinds of depth to it,
but it's filled with, like,
love.
Actually it's brisket,
but call it what you want.
WOMAN: The Asian fusion mix
and then the barbecue.
They have something
on the menu for everyone.
My regular here
is the ribs, for sure.
He smokes them just right.
Sticky bourbon sauce on 'em.
I've had three napkins
taken away from me already.
We're going to do some major
Southern food right now.
Okay.
These are spareribs.
Got it.
Cut in the St. Louis style.
Yeah.
The dry rub we made before?
Yes.
Dig it! Let's go to the smoker.
This is four to five hours
at 225 degrees.
We are going to make
our honey bourbon glaze.
The bourbon.
Warm it just a tad.
Tad is not a real
culinary term, by the way.
We'll see.
Light it.
Burn off a little
of the alcohol.
Yeah. Honey. Brown sugar.
Brown sugar.
And we're going to
pour over the ribs.
We don't really pour it.
We just lightly brush it.
What's next?
Bacon, barbecue sauce,
and some butter, white onion,
fresh chopped garlic.
Some cooked chopped bacon.
Ketchup.
Pour it all in there.
Don't hold back!
Okay. Amber beer.
What are you saving
the last little bit?
Some for my homies?
You know.
What, Limp Noodles
and Stale Bread
aren't rolling
through here, are they, Dawg?
Some apple cider vinegar.
Brisket drippings.
Molasses.
You're saving it again.
You're killing me, Smalls.
When you're messing
with my molasses,
you're messing
with my emotion.
Oh, I know.
Worcestershire?
Sugar. Kosher salt.
Fresh ground pepper.
Got it. Cook all this down?
Yep.
Blend it and cook it
30 minutes.
Ta da!
Here are the ribs.
Nice bark on that.
Yeah. Make 'em all pretty.
Gorgeous.
And here is the finished
barbecue sauce.
A little green onion,
and it is done.
Nice big, meaty rib.
Nice smoke ring.
Wow, cooked perfectly.
Super tender. Good smoke.
The barbecue sauce
is crazy.
[ Laughter ]
What? Don't judge.
You would so do it
if it was you.
The barbecue sauce adds
another component to the dish.
It's rich.
Tons of bacon in it.
Nice little kick
with the molasses.
That's really good.
These ribs are succulent.
MAN: The honey bourbon sauce
is really good.
It's got a sweetness.
It is sticky.
It's going to get messy.
It's nice.
Tacos, table 5.
Some of the best food
that you can eat in Juneau.
If you like Asian,
and you like barbecue,
and you like creative,
out of a funky little joint
that was somebody's home,
with two really cool people,
this is your place.
Thank you.
Up next,
in Cambridge, Massachusetts...
That's a culinary submarine
in the Flavor Town navy.
Fried chicken sporting
Nashville heat.
My eyes are watering.
Gumbo taking you from
Bean Town to Bourbon Street.
Hitting it out of the park.
Plus a curve ball
you just don't see coming.
Where else can you get messy,
nasty, and tiki all together?
This is brought to you by
the law offices
of Messy, Nasty, and Tiki.
♪♪
So we're here
in Cambridge, Mass --
[ Whistles ]
Hold up now, son.
Just 'cause I let you drive,
doesn't mean it's your show.
I thought we were gonna -
I know, we -- okay.
Anyway, Hunter, I love joints
with the name Highland in it.
We've been to the Highlander,
so that's in Atlanta.
We've been to Highland Tavern,
that's in Colorado.
So outside of Boston
I hear about this joint
that's doing killer barbecue,
some awesome gumbo,
and real-deal fried chicken.
This is Highland Fried.
One day, this is my show.
Come on, Hunter.
I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
Fried chicken biscuit sandwich.
WOMAN: Definitely not
the traditional food
that you would find
in Boston and Cambridge.
What kind of restaurant is it?
Barbecue fried food.
-Yee haw!
-It's Southern with a twist.
FIERI: Whatever it is,
it's definitely clickin' --
or should I say cluckin' --
with Chef Mark Romano.
I have another restaurant
in Somerville.
We started doing fried chicken,
and we won like best chicken
in Boston.
And now,
since I bought this place,
we just kind of wanted
to focus on the fried chicken.
This fried chicken
is great on its own,
but when you add
that Nashville hot sauce,
it takes it to another level.
MAN: I don't know what they're
doing to these birds,
but it's really good.
Let's get on the train
to Flavor Town, baby. Okay.
Okay, we're going to make
our brine
for our Nashville fried chicken.
So we got water here.
Add salt.
Hormone free,
all natural chicken.
Do you freeze it?
No, no, it's fresh.
It just crosses the road.
Anybody?
[ Laughs ]
Then we're going to
add buttermilk to it.
Let that sit overnight.
The next step is?
Our dredge.
All-purpose flour. Corn flour.
Cornstarch. Salt.
Black pepper.
Ground coriander. Celery salt.
Old Bay seasoning.
Add our buttermilk chicken.
Let it rest for about
at least a half hour,
and then we're going to
put it into a pressure fryer.
That's a culinary submarine
in the Flavor Town navy.
-I love it.
-Let's make the Nashville hot.
Guajillo chilies. Anchos.
Scotch Bonnet. Habanero chilies.
Trinidad scorpion peppers.
Our secret weapon,
Carolina reaper. Really hot.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Who's going to eat this sauce?
Brown sugar.
Some salt, paprika, cayenne.
The cayenne is like a dinner
mint compared to the...
Dark chili powder.
Chicken stock.
And we're just going to let this
sit here and simmer?
Going to let
this reduce by half.
All right.
We have some Dijon mustard.
Puree it with some chicken fat,
and duck fat,
and whatever else
kind of fat we can find.
Whatever fat you find?
That's a paint remover.
We got a shake, too.
A Nashville hot shake?
All those dried chilies with
a little bit of brown sugar.
And we hit that powder
on top of the chicken.
Oh, I thought you meant
a shake like you drink,
like a milkshake.
No, no, no.
It's like a spice shake.
I was like, there's no way
I'm drinking that.
[ Whistles ]
What are we going
to serve alongside the chicken?
Our buttermilk biscuit.
What's the biscuit magic?
We're going to
make our dry mix.
All-purpose flour.
Vegetable shortening.
Salt. A little sugar.
Baking soda. Baking powder.
FIERI:
This is going to go get frozen,
then we're going to take it and
incorporate it with the butter.
Grated. Frozen.
We want to keep it
as cold as possible,
so when you bake
off the biscuits,
they go this way
as opposed to this way.
Got it.
It's got some
ice-cold buttermilk.
We're going to roll it out
three times.
Fold it once over here.
This is kind of your lacquering
that happens
when you're the croissant.
Yeah.
So that's two times.
One more time and we're
going to be good to go.
Here we go.
Yeah, it's a half-hour show.
Welcome to the biscuit hour.
It's Guy and Hunter.
Freeze 'em again.
Bake 'em off at 350.
That's it.
We got our Nashville
hot sauce right here.
Gonna put our three pieces in.
Take our little shake here.
Put a little more ha,
ha, ha, ha.
And on the biscuits,
we take a little butter
and a little drizzle of honey.
There you go.
Three-piece Nashville hot
and collard greens.
♪♪
How we lookin'?
That's good.
You got really good heat.
Not screamin' heat.
Getting a little --
My eyes are watering.
You watching
"Me and Marley" again?
"Marley and Me"?
That's what I thought.
I like the balanced heat.
Not too over the top.
Little bit of sugar
in that helps.
It's lighting you up.
Delicious, though.
Crunchy.
Juicy.
You've done such a great job
putting the brine on this.
There's a lot
of moisture in there.
Um, um, um.
Fried chicken dance.
Flaky biscuit.
It's really fluffy and airy.
That's delicious.
I mean like --
Appreciate it.
We're getting some to go.
Without question.
MAN: Nashville hot chicken,
you're not just getting
blasted with heat.
You're getting the flavor and
the juiciness in the chicken.
WOMAN:
The biscuits are delicious.
They're really thick
on the outside but very soft.
WOMAN: I would describe
Highland Fried
as my neighborhood fried
chicken and tiki joint.
WOMAN:
There's blender cocktails.
Shaved ice cocktails.
It's pretty great.
MAN: You feel like,
"I'm in the Caribbean,"
this is the spot to be.
-When we come back,
we're going to get into
a whole 'nother dish.
Throwing some Cajun
into the Southern tiki mix.
-Gumbo!
-If you love gumbo,
this is where you need
to get it.
See you in a bit.
Welcome back to "Triple D."
We're out here
outside of Boston.
We just had some killer chicken
over here at Highland Fried.
The menu is a little bit
of Southern food,
a little bit
of fried chicken,
and then some other things
sprinkled in.
What's your favorite
thing on the menu?
The one and only gumbo.
Hot food! Let's go!
The gumbo is very smoky,
but in the best way possible.
-It's so unique.
-Chef, what's up next?
We're going to make
some of our smoky gumbo.
First step is?
For our chicken thighs,
we make a rub.
Paprika. Brown sugar.
White sugar.
Salt. Black pepper. Cayenne.
Chili powder. And cumin.
Now we're going
to prep our ribs.
Salt.
Cracked black pepper?
Yeah. Granulated garlic.
Paprika, okay.
And a little onion.
Slather it on there.
Both are going to go
to the smoker?
Smoke everything at 250.
Got it.
When they're done, take 'em,
cool 'em, shred 'em,
and that's the basis
of the gumbo?
That's right.
That goes in the gumbo.
All right, Chef,
let's get into it.
We're going to start off
with our roux.
We make ours with a little
olive oil and canola oil.
And flour.
So we keep it dairy free.
Because, you know, there's a lot
of allergies these days.
Yeah, we're really worried
about your health down here
at Highland Fried.
Going to cook
our veggies over here.
We got the holy trinity.
Onions, celery, and bell pepper.
Garlic.
And we put our Andouille --
Andouille in,
let that render down with it.
A blackening spice.
Fresh thyme and oregano.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Some bay leaf
and some gumbo filé.
From the leaf
of the sassafras tree.
Gonna add the dark roux.
Chicken stock.
Smoked pork jelly.
Love it.
Fresh tomatoes.
And we're going to put
in our pork shrapnel.
Pulled chicken.
Okra?
Yeah.
We're going to let this simmer
for about 45 minutes to an hour.
All right,
ready for some gumbo.
See this line right here?
That's yours.
Don't start.
Um. Oh, yeah.
♪♪
What do you think?
Well, the fact I took about
15 consecutive bites
out of that might
just say a little bit.
I like it.
The smokiness of the ribs
and the chicken makes
the entire dish right there.
Hunter is exactly right.
Real big, beautiful pieces
of barbecue in there.
You have enough consistency
in the sauce
from the roux
and from that pork jelly.
It's silky,
it's unctuous,
without being heavy
and too rich.
Oh, my gosh, bro.
Hitting it out of the park!
Thanks, man. Two gumbos.
Pick it up now.
The texture is just amazing.
You get a softness from the meat
which is really good.
WOMAN: The roux is very velvety
and rich, it's wonderful.
ROMANO: Two Brussels sprouts
buffalo fried.
Where else can you get messy,
nasty, and tiki all together?
Messy, nasty, and tiki.
It sounds like a new
place to open.
This is brought to you
by the law offices
of Messy, Nasty & Tiki.
Hot food, please.
This was lights out.
It's a state of mind,
Highland Fried.
Seriously.
Dude, state of mind it is.
You guys got to
come check it out.
Coming up in Sparks, Nevada
This is going to get
interesting in a second.
Award-worthy barbecue --
He's got trophies that are just
used to wedge open a window.
Moonshine sauce.
You do it like that, son.
And chicken wing nachos.
That's one of the most unique
dishes I've seen on "Triple D."
Hunter, I'm putting you to the
chicken water chug challenge.
Hunter and I arm wrestle.
One of us has to take
a shot of the chicken water.
Let's go.
That's a dumb bet, no.
What are you --
No.
♪♪
So I'm here
in Sparks, Nevada,
just about a mile
or two outside of Reno.
Now, when you're cruising
through a town like this,
and you drive by and you
see a barbecue trailer,
and then you see yourself
an old hickory pit.
An old hickory pit.
And another old hickory pit.
I bet you they're doing
some real-deal barbecue.
This is Carolina Kitchen
and Barbecue Company.
Half pound pork plate for John.
I base all my barbecues
off of Carolina Kitchen.
WOMAN:
You can smell the smoke,
and it just calls you in.
Three-rib platter.
How do you describe
the place to people?
I always put this guys
in the great category.
WOMAN:
We just load up on barbecue
and I have to waddle
myself to the car.
FIERI: But Chef Clay Cobb didn't
start out
as a 'cue connoisseur.
After working in fine
dining back East,
he moved to Nevada, opened up
this joint with his mom,
and got back to his family's
Southern roots.
His dad was from the South.
What kind of barbecue
you guys doing?
Carolina-style barbecue.
What kind of wood
are we smoking with?
Almond.
Really?
You're doing pulled pork.
You're doing wings.
And then people
demanded brisket.
Demanded?
And we decided to
step up the game,
use Wagyu brisket.
Your Wagyu brisket platter.
Super tender. Super juicy.
-Wonderful smoke.
-I've eaten myself into regret
with this brisket.
-All right, let's get into it.
We're just going to trim
the brisket up.
And we're going
to make the rub.
Okay.
Kosher salt.
Coarse black pepper.
Of course.
Granulated garlic.
Mix it up.
A little mustard schmear.
I have seen some liberal
rubbing of briskets in my life.
This guy might take the cake.
Let it tack up a little bit,
you know, an hour.
Go to the smoke.
215, about 15 hours.
We're going to wrap it up,
finish it off
until it hits about 203.
Pull it?
Yeah. We let them rest
for an hour, hour-and-a-half.
You have got to explain
to me what we're doing.
Collard greens.
What happened to the greens?
Well, they're chopped
and blanched.
Where'd you learn this method?
Believe it or not,
it was my Italian college buddy.
That's a new one for me.
You learn something
from everybody.
Let's see how they taste.
All right. Bacon.
Onions. Sweat the onions.
Add the greens. And some water.
And some beef base.
That's a new one.
Let this go for about two hours.
Apple cider vinegar.
Some salt.
We're off to the races.
Next step?
Moonshine barbecue sauce.
You mean, like, legit?
Moonshine.
Shine-shine?
Yeah.
♪♪
Smooth.
Yeah?
It's good, though.
Should get a second opinion
on that from the camera
and just see what you think.
Camera, what do you think?
There you go.
See, the camera's not driving.
That's right.
Camera! Camera! Stick with me.
Ketchup. Seasoned salt.
Moonshine.
You do it like that, son.
Liquid smoke. Cider vinegar.
Worcestershire sauce.
Hot sauce with some sugar.
I like this sauce.
Just bring it to a boil,
and we're good to go.
That's some
good-looking brisket.
I mean, that is about
as juicy and tender.
That is killer.
Some of the best brisket
I've seen outside
of Texas, actually.
Not that I think
this brisket needs sauce.
Mmm. In the world of collards,
boy I'll tell you what.
Tender and cooked down...
But still enough texture.
That's great, man.
This is like you've been working
with a pit master
down in Texas a while.
The real deal. Well done, man.
Thanks.
The meat is melt
in your mouth.
It's got this fantastic
peppercorn.
MAN: The moonshine sauce adds a
little sweetness and smokiness.
Good greens?
Very good.
MAN: Clay is definitely
a world-class chef.
He's got a great
catering business going.
FIERI: And he's no stranger
to a little competition.
They've won all
over northern Nevada.
He's got trophies that are just
used to wedge open a window.
I mean, they're just
laying around here.
I think someone used one
as a stepstool a second ago.
We did the chicken
wing competition.
We did first place
for about five years.
Five-wing nachos are up.
The smoked wing nachos
are awesome.
WOMAN: Everything that you
usually see on nachos
now suddenly is on chicken.
They're just devastating.
We have our chicken wings.
We're going to make
our smoked wing nachos.
We're going to rub them
down with some oil.
Oil only?
That's it.
No salt, no pepper now?
Not yet because we're
going to deep fry 'em.
We don't want that
char flavor on the rub.
Okay.
That's a big wing.
There's a couple wingless
pterodactyls out there.
Smoke them for about
45 minutes, 275.
Okay. Come out of the smoker
into the fryer.
All right, what are you into?
Dry rub.
Which is half Cajun
seasoning, half rib rub.
This is our Cajun seasoning.
Paprika. Salt.
Granulated garlic. Black pepper.
White pepper. Onion powder.
Ground thyme. Dry mustard.
And chili powder.
Got it.
And we're gonna go rib rub.
Salt. White pepper. Paprika.
Black pepper. Chili powder.
This is going to get
interesting in a second.
Sugar?
White sugar.
Brown sugar clumps.
Granulated garlic.
You don't find the burn
on the white sugar?
No, I like it.
You've won competitions
with this rub?
I have.
I won't tell anybody. Shh.
Do a little half
and half here.
And this is what we're going
to sprinkle on the wings?
Hit it with some moonshine
barbecue sauce.
Cheese. Bacon.
Pop it in the oven for a minute.
Okay.
Where are the tortillas?
There are no tortillas.
The wing is the nacho.
It has all the toppings on it.
All right. This I gotta see.
Diced tomato.
How you going to get the tomato
to stay on the chicken wing?
Green onion. Spicy ranch.
Sour cream.
♪♪
It's a really good wing.
I love the smoke.
A little fry to it.
Who needs a tortilla chip?
You get the crunch
of the outside of the wing.
The cheese melts
on really nice.
Then you have the bacon
sticking to it
so you get all best of
both worlds all over it.
You hit that moonshine sauce
on there, which is dynamite.
You get yourself
some of the cool sour cream.
That's one of the most
unique dishes I've seen on
"Triple D," and you
actually pulled it off.
Well done.
Thank you.
There's so much
going on here,
but it all works really,
really well.
Sour cream on a wing
is delicious.
And it's something
I haven't had.
They're amazing.
It's crazy, isn't it?
Yes.
It is a nacho that
became a chicken wing, or a
chicken wing that became --
Anyhow.
Dixie dog for pickup.
Makes you happy
to come down here.
Lights out. Game changer.
Insane.
A bunch of smokers,
making a lot of people happy.
The real deal. Check 'em out.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry,
there's plenty more
"Triple D" joints
all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
I just love pho.
It's so pho-n to make.
Pho-get about it.
Do you have any pho ball teams
up here, or is it too cold?
How many phos has that been?