You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy,
that one joint you checked out
in that one city when you were
doing 'Triple D' --
how are they doing?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[ Engine revs ]
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
Oh, I love this!
...we're going for primo pie...
Look at that.
...to terrific Thai.
I'm gonna drown
in my own drool.
Like in a family-run spot
in Hawaii...
This is the bomb.
...taking their
taste of Thailand up a notch.
To see that you've gone
next level, that's killer.
And a Dallas joint
gone to the dogs...
Are you crazy?
Yeah.
...spreading their fired-up
flavors all over town.
-Fresh and funky?
-Yeah.
And a winning combo
in Washington D.C...
Whoo-hoo!
...putting their unique
spin on the plate...
Rock star all the way.
...and on the table.
-You're good at ping-pong?
-No.
[ Laughs ]
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, back in 2012, "Triple D"
was at the North Shore of Oahu,
shot this awesome
little Thai place.
And we came back
a couple of years later,
and we found out
it had closed.
What has gone on?
This place was off the hook.
There's no way
it could have closed.
Good news is we found out
it reopened
just a few months later
in the downtown area of Waikiki.
It's time to revisit
our friends at Opal.
♪♪
Opal is just awesome.
Been coming here
since I saw it on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Opal exceeds even the
finest restaurants in Bangkok.
FIERI: That's 'cause owner
Opal Sirichandhra
knows what he's doing
when it comes to Thai,
and so does his wife, Aoi.
And back then, even his son
Leo was pitching in.
You help, too?
Yeah, busboy/server.
Busboy slash server,
in case you didn't pick it up.
-What's up, brother?
-How are you?
So, seven years ago,
we shoot Opal.
You were this big.
Are you working
in the restaurant at all?
Like twice,
three times a week.
That's good.
I mean, I remember walking
in there that day.
Your whole family was great.
The food was outrageous.
The first thing we're gonna
start off with is the Pad Thai?
Pad Thai.
Let's go.
You got this
high BTU burner.
I mean, this thing
is smoking hot.
I'd have this right next
to my bed if I could.
We're gonna do
the tofu, egg.
-Pickled radish?
-Pickled radish.
Shrimp.
Noodle.
Fish sauce.
Paprika.
Green onion.
Bean sprout.
I'm gonna drown
in my own drool.
Lime. Peanut.
Now --
Wait.
Aah?
I want to make sure he eats
the way we eat in Thailand.
You got to taste the food
and then squeeze the lime.
It's hot, though.
Oh, really?
What, are you waving
goodbye to it?
Mmm!
Second stage.
[ Slurps ]
And what's
the third stage?
Now I need a chili.
Aah!
Not overly cooked.
Everything stay crispy, fresh.
That's just what
I was gonna say.
So, last time Guy came by,
we made traditional Pad Thai.
A savory, garlicky version
of the Pad Thai.
So, we're gonna make it
with chicken and shrimp,
egg, garlic, and chili,
rice noodle, fish sauce
with lots of fresh garlic
and the pickled garlic.
Green onion.
♪♪
All right,
country-style.
MAN: It has
a good spice to it
without being so hot
that you sweat to death.
Each of the ingredients was
perfectly cooked, just superb.
I've had a lot
of Pad Thai, man.
I've not had a chance
to Thai this.
Oh, I'm glad
you tried it.
FIERI: Without question,
one of our favorite
Thai restaurants
we'd been to.
We come back to the islands
every year,
and we were gearing up
to go to your restaurant,
and it was gone, and we didn't
have any way to find you.
It was a travesty.
What happened?
We just decided to pick up
and be a part of the community
in a different location.
So you left the North Shore,
came over to Honolulu?
Yes.
So you have a bigger kitchen,
a bigger restaurant?
Yes.
So you can do more?
Exactly.
Oh, bro.
FIERI:
Like his wife's Khao Soi.
This is Thai tradition
from North of Thailand.
Then we add...
MAN: You've got some sweetness.
You've got some savory.
It's a perfect dish.
WOMAN:
It has soft noodle, and then
you've got fried ones on top.
It's just really nice having
that extra crispy texture.
And he pairs it
with the garlic wings.
They just are
perfect together.
What are we making?
Glazed garlic chicken wing,
classic style.
How do we start?
Fried chicken wing.
No batter.
Now we're gonna make
the sauce.
Lots of garlic, chili paste,
vegetable broth.
Let it cook.
[ Whistles ]
So, you make the sauce
a day ahead of time
to let all the flavors marry?
Exactly.
And now we're
ready to go...
In a hot pan.
Let it cook.
Put some more fresh garlic.
We're gonna do the basil.
Firecracker go.
[ Oil popping ]
Oh, too bad I wasn't over
for that part.
♪♪
Look at that.
Holy moly.
This is the bomb.
What are you looking at?
Your tattoo.
Oh. I just thought you were
seeing that my gut was growing.
No.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: I mean, I remember
walking in there that day,
and you're this tiny little
hole-in-the-wall joint,
and now to see that you've gone
next level, that's killer.
The people, they come eat.
They happy.
They spread the word.
I'm very happy, so I'm gonna
spread the word, too.
Thank you.
Just by a few 10 million
people a night, but...
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Up next,
a Dallas joint blowing up...
This is a whirlwind.
...taking their
pasta and pizza...
Ha, ha!
...all over town.
This is where it's
gonna get cool.
FIERI: Back in 2011, my burger
buds from Twisted Root in Dallas
told me about a new kid
on their block.
Amatriciana's coming out.
FIERI: This restaurant rookie
had just quit his day job
to start slinging pies,
and now he's dealing his dishes
at eight different locations.
This is the one
and only Cane Rosso.
Billy Ray up.
The pizza is just really
different
than anything else
you could get in Dallas.
It was no surprise to us
when it was on "Triple D"
because we were obsessed
with the food
before it was even famous.
Gangster.
Jay hated his cubicle so much
that he created a pizza empire.
FIERI: He's talking about former
IT sales guy, Jay Jerrier,
who, when I met him,
had just quit his day job.
JERRIER: I've been in
the restaurant business
for exactly 9 1/2 months.
This is our
first restaurant.
You crazy?
Yeah, I know. Insane.
Cane Rosso is named after
my first dog.
The Hungarian Pointers,
they have red fur,
and Cane Rosso means
"red dog" in Italian.
How many dogs do
you have?
We have Gus, who's on the menu.
Delia's on the menu.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Make sure you say
this the right way.
Yeah, I guess that
didn't come off right.
They are honored
on the menu.
Out of all the things
you could have named
your pizza place after,
you named it after dogs.
I know.
Don't tell my kids.
We are gonna make our
bacon marmalade
for our Delia pizza.
We're gonna start with
a little olive oil in the pan
and just throw this in here.
Minced shallots, garlic,
Calabrian chilies,
cherry vinegar,
chili paste.
Finish it off
with some sugar.
Cook down...
Until it gets to, like,
a jelly or jam-like
or marmalade-like
consistency.
So, we're gonna
make our dough.
I'm gonna
go out on a limb.
Okay.
I think this is
my birthday,
and this is just a big surprise,
and he's giving me this.
This mixer? Yeah.
We need a bigger one anyway.
Good. See?
We'll load it up for you.
Get it in the back
of the car.
That's a verbal contract.
That is a verbal contract,
and that's on tape.
Water, Sicilian sea salt,
and we add our Caputo flour.
Caputo flour --
the double-zero,
high-gluten flour.
And then the yeast.
We mix it totally
for 25 minutes.
Then we'll ball it up,
let it proof at room temperature
for eight to 12 hours.
Got it.
Just give it
a little stretch.
Wow, that is just thin
and fast, man.
Fresh mozzarella,
bacon marmalade,
roasted grape tomatoes,
a little squirt of olive oil,
a little bit of basil.
Going into an oven
at what temp?
About 900 degrees.
900-degree oven.
This is where
it's gonna get cool.
So, this is
60 to 70 seconds.
Ha, ha! Look at that.
We add a little arugula,
a bit of olive oil.
It's ready to go
to a table.
♪♪
The sweet, smoky, salty
bacon marmalade that goes in...
Mmm!
The arugula
for a little pepper.
This is a whirlwind. This is --
This is -- This -- Ah.
[ Mouth full ]
I'm at a loss for words.
And it's still one of the most
popular pizzas on our menu.
Nice job, brother.
FIERI: But when he's not
naming pies for his pups,
he's pulling out
the pop culture.
[ Imitating Arnold
Schwarzenegger ]
It's not a tumor.
"Those aren't the droids
you're looking for."
A lot of great movie references
in the shoot today.
"220, 221."
"Whatever it takes."
Nice.
I've seen that movie.
He didn't know I speak
in '80s movie references.
The Billy Ray Valentine pizza
comes from "Trading Places,"
the Dan Aykroyd
and Eddie Murphy movie.
When the Dukes are explaining
to Billy Ray Valentine
how the market works and they're
talking about pork belly,
and so it has chopped
bacon and bacon marmalade.
But we're gonna make
our vodka sauce.
Start off with some onions,
cook them down,
hit it with some garlic,
vodka,
tomatoes, basil,
and heavy cream.
Season it with salt.
We'll let that simmer down
for about 30 minutes
so it gets nice and thick.
Little basil, fresh mozzarella
that we make in-house.
So you make your own mozz.
We do.
You've got it cut
and rinsed.
Add our hot, salted water.
Just keep doing this
till we get a nice big mass.
This --
Whoa!
It's a messy job,
and this is where it
all went horribly wrong.
[ Laughter ]
So, you roll it
into itself.
Drop it in some ice water.
It'll tighten up.
Let it sit there
for 24 hours.
Then we're gonna drain it
and cut it for our pizza.
Now we're gonna add
a few Sweety Drop peppers,
bacon, bacon marmalade.
Now the pie's ready
to go in the oven.
Finish it with a little
extra-virgin olive oil,
Parmesan, fresh parsley.
Here's the Billy Ray Valentine.
WOMAN:
The Billy Ray Valentine pizza
is a mixture
of smokiness and cheesy.
The vodka sauce gives it
kind of a little savory taste.
Anytime you get two different
kinds of bacon on a pizza,
it's aces in my book.
FIERI: And that pork's not just
top of the pizza.
Coming up...
Porkilicious.
It's a new word.
...pig-tastic pasta.
That's what they need to start
selling it at the fair.
...and finger-lickin' fritters.
Mmm!
Carbonara's up.
I'm here in Dallas, Texas,
in a very well-known "Triple D"
area known as Deep Ellum,
home to "Triple D" alum
Twisted Root,
who in 2012, gave me a hot tip
on an off-the-hook spot
new to their block, Cane Rosso.
Let's get ready to mangia.
FIERI: You happen to be
across the street
from one of the coolest
burger joints you can find,
not just in Dallas but in
the country, Twisted Root.
Right.
But when they told me
the space was across
from Twisted Root,
I had seen them on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
and I knew they had
a great lunch business.
What a great show that is.
And while this
ex-cubicle-sitting chef
had only been in the biz
for 9 1/2 months,
he's certified
at Pizza Napolitana,
and he's hand-cranking
premium pasta.
Now we're gonna make
our fresh pasta
for our Pasta Amatriciana.
Which is, of all the pasta
dishes in the world,
probably in my top three.
This is the same flour
we use for our pizza.
Super high-gluten flour.
Gonna get a lot of
great chew out of that.
We add the eggs,
pinch of salt.
This is how you do it every day
for your restaurant?
Every morning.
Let's start adding
a little bit water?
Yeah, we can get it
to come together.
Then we'll wrap it,
store it,
bring it out,
start running it through.
I make a lot of pasta at home.
I know it's hard to tell.
You guys think
I'm pretty much just...
A pretty face?
Exactly.
Feel the pain.
Feel the burn.
So, we make our pancetta.
Little pork belly?
A little sea salt.
You're gonna get
all this great,
unctious,
pig-inicious flavor
that's gonna
come out of the --
It's a new word.
Work with it.
[ Laughs ]
Cure for three days,
put it in a 325-degree oven
anywhere from 60 to 90 minutes,
and we will just --
Oh! Got to get to get
right into that.
That's what they need
to start selling at the fair.
Get these kids off the candy.
Mmm! Go right ahead.
Do whatever you got to do now.
Dice this up.
A little extra-virgin olive oil.
Pancetta.
A few onions in there.
Touch of pasta water.
San Marzano tomatoes,
red chili flakes, Parmesan.
Drop our pasta.
Cook for about a minute.
Drop it in the pan.
More Parmesan on top of that.
It's ready to go.
It's got all the right
principles, man.
Great pasta.
Nice texture to it, nice chew.
Got pig-tastic
house-cured pancetta.
It's simple. It's delicate.
Did a good job.
All right, dude.
This is all fresh
and good food.
Fresh and funky.
Yeah.
JERRIER: I never thought we'd be
this popular and this busy.
We went from one restaurant
to now eight. It's crazy.
Order up.
JERRIER: We also started
an ice cream company.
FIERI: Not to mention
some adds to the old menu.
We're gonna make our zucchini
and artichoke fritters.
In Texas, the rule is
if it's green, it's trouble.
If it's fried, get double.
Start with a little bit
of water, butter, and salt
and then flour to make a roux.
Add the eggs.
Mix it on medium speed.
Fontina cheese, Pecorino cheese,
roasted garlic, parsley.
Chopped artichokes,
shredded zucchini.
Then we're gonna put
the dough into a pastry bag
so we can pipe it
into the fryer.
About 14 little nuggets.
My favorite culinary terms.
[ Laughs ] Right.
Take these from the fryer.
Salt, parsley,
fresh-grated Parmesan.
Give them a little toss.
And everybody likes to have
a dip for them, as well,
so we're gonna make
our farmhouse dip.
Start off with copious
amounts of mayonnaise,
sour cream, buttermilk,
garlic powder,
onion powder, salt, oregano,
fresh-chopped Italian parsley,
a little dill,
some red-wine vinegar.
Now we're just gonna
whisk it up.
Zucchini and artichoke fritters
with our farmhouse dip.
WOMAN: They have this really
great crunch to them
but a lot of cheese
on the inside.
I immediately was grabbing
a second one
before I even finished
[Laughing] the first one.
The dip just enhances it,
takes it to the next level.
I want to know why they don't
have, like, bacon toothpaste...
I think they do.
...or bacon deodorant.
Guy really helped build us
this empire.
Mmm!
It's allowed us to take some of
the profits from the restaurants
and start something
we're passionate about,
which is a dog rescue.
FIERI: In the form of a
3,000-square-foot facility,
which has helped save
over 500 furry friends.
Who's a good girl?
I love that they've opened
the dog rescue
and made that part
of their mission.
It's a really unique way to
give back to the city of Dallas.
-Excellent job, man.
-All right. Thanks, man.
Excellent job.
I don't know
what I like better --
what he's doing
with the pasta and pies
or what he's doing
for those pups.
Now, coming up
in Washington, D.C.,
a pizza/Ping-Pong spot...
Oh, outstanding.
...blowing your typical toppings
out of the water.
I will fight you
for the rest of that.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Now, most people think
of politics when they think
of Washington D.C.,
but not this guy.
I'm thinking about pizza
and Ping-Pong...
Pick up, please.
...a combo I ran into
back in 2010.
Oh!
And don't worry,
they're still serving up both.
This is Comet Ping Pong.
♪♪
Guy came in, and so once
I found out that he was here,
it made me feel like this
is the spot to be in.
The food is fantastic.
Who doesn't love Ping-Pong
and pizza?
I mean, come on.
FIERI: That's what owner
James Alefantis thought
when he opened
this joint in 2006.
I grew up baking,
plus I love playing Ping-Pong.
I'd be happy to play with you.
You're good at ping pong?
No.
[ Laughs ]
Not with any dude that owns
a Ping-Pong pizza joint.
Guy came, hung out
with us all day.
We had super great fun
cooking together.
We make a pizza
called the Yalie,
which is made
with littleneck clams.
And Yalie stands for...
Yale. 4 hostesses
all got accepted to Yale.
From here?
Fast track to Yale.
Good.
I think we're on almost
10 hosts or hostesses
getting into the Ivy league.
So, we take our
littleneck clams...
[ Clattering ]
pour them into here --
Awesome sound.
Bunch of
whole garlic, lemons,
and then we got fresh thyme,
bunch of olive oil.
As soon as they start
popping open.
Pour them out, shuck them
out of the shells.
-The "chells."
Yep. Remember to put
your application in
if you want to go to Yale.
The "chells."
Wow. One for me.
[ Slurps ] Mmm!
Don't eat all these clams, man.
We got to make some pizzas.
Oh, those are good.
He ate like 25 clams,
half our order.
Look, six clams left.
Salt.
Right on the dough.
A little bit of pepper,
slow-cooked onions, garlic oil.
Garlic's been sliced
and cooked down very slowly.
Fresh thyme.
And just get
the clams and...
Chuck them on there.
And everything goes in
the super-duper killer oven.
Getting way back.
Oh, I love this!
Look at the crust right on
the bottom of that thing.
Mmm! Oh!
[ Mouth full ] Okay,
it is fantastic.
I will fight you
for the rest of that.
[ Laughs ]
A lot of their pizzas
are pretty out there.
ALEFANTIS: We're going to make
the Softy,
which is
a soft-shell crab pizza.
We're gonna roll our dough.
It's the exact same recipe.
Guy and I made it together.
High-gluten Caputo, Italian
flour, whole-wheat flour.
So a little color,
a little texture.
A bunch of salt, dry yeast.
Straight in.
Secret ingredient --
diastatic malt powder.
It helps with the rise and adds
a little bit of chew to it.
Water -- that's it.
We tossed the doughs
around together. [ Chuckles ]
It was quite fun.
Nice.
With the soft-shell crab pizza,
we get these nice
roasted pieces of garlic.
Then you take an lot of leeks,
which are cooked in butter.
And then you take
your whole crab,
put it right on top
of your pizza.
Put right here in the oven.
You've got to make sure that
this crab is nice and cooked.
Now we finish with fresh-grated
Parmesan cheese, parsley,
some fresh lemon,
and there you go.
Softy's up.
The soft shell-crab kind of,
like, explodes with flavor
in your mouth.
The dough is really great,
kind of pillowy with some crunch
that takes the idea
that you eat from the region.
It's as farm-to-table
as you can get it.
Yeah. We harvest 4,000 pounds
of organic tomatoes every year.
We make every single thing
from scratch.
Enjoy.
ALEFANTIS: We're gonna make
ricotta cheese.
All you do is take milk,
buttermilk.
Let me give you
some help with that.
That'd be good.
So I'm gonna
chug the buttermilk.
Go, go!
Whoo-hoo!
You just see it starts
to pull away.
Yeah, curding away.
So, what do you say while
we're watching this, we go...
Play some Ping-Pong?
...eat some clams.
[ Laughs ]
So this pizza's called
the Stanley.
Salt, pepper, red sauce,
mozzarella, roasted peppers.
This is
the fennel sausage.
Then we can see
how our ricotta turned out.
Mmm! Nice and creamy
and light. Dynamite.
-That's it.
-Into the oven?
It should be good.
Look at that.
♪♪
Ah, outstanding.
Rock star all the way.
I love the menu here 'cause
it's so versatile.
He added the duck pizza
to the menu. Really good.
The Barbequack is a newer pizza.
Start with fresh duck legs.
Give it a nice salting.
Set it aside
while you combine the sauce.
Brown sugar, red-wine vinegar,
balsamic vinegar.
Pour it all over these legs.
Put it right into the pizza oven
and cook it overnight.
Get a nice base
of this garlic oil on here.
And then we also
use melted onions.
Here's our duck.
Some of this nice fat
that's cooked with the duck.
Cheddar cheese adds,
like, a nice richness.
We finish our Barbequack pizza
with a pickled onion.
Barbequack up.
The duck is amazing. It's very
tender and juicy and moist.
WOMAN:
You have that barbecue flavor,
and the pickled onions add,
like, a really nice touch.
FIERI:
Quality real ingredients.
This is how it's
supposed to be done.
If you live
north of the Equator,
you have to come up here,
and anybody south,
you have an extra day.
So no wonder Ping-Pong pairs
so well with this pizza.
Got to work off
all those calories
after eating all those pies...
...just like the wood-fired eats
at Cane Rosso in Dallas
and the top-notch Thai
from Opal in Oahu.
Plus, we'll keep adding
to the menu
when we visit more places
right here on "Triple D Nation."
But building these strands is
what we're really trying to --
Yeah, where we get
nice and...
nice and stretchy.
[ Laughs ]
Do I got it?
Is it gone?
Yeah.
No, it looks good.