Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Let the games begin.
...it's a full platter
of meat...
Oh, my gosh,
this is so good.
...that goes way beyond
the beef...
That's a butcher's rainbow
in Flavortown.
...like out-of-bounds ox tail
in Virginia...
I knew it!
...Vermont lamb
and fiery wings...
Me likey wingy.
...and in Ottawa, Canada...
[ Imitates explosion ]
...an outrageous take on duck...
It's outstanding.
...and a visit to Pork-topia.
Shut the front door,
the back door, the side door,
and all the windows.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in Ottawa, Canada,
about 10 minutes
from downtown --
It's right that way --
in an area that was known
as Mechanicsville.
Now, back in the day,
it was kind of an unsavory area,
but man, it's really
made a change,
and it's attracted people
like this husband-and-wife team
who took an office
and turned it into a restaurant
where they're doing smoked,
cured meats
that got everybody talking.
This is Meat Press.
Pork belly's going in.
Meat Press is the quintessential
smoked-meat sandwich place.
Everything's made from scratch.
Smoked duck's on.
Creativity coming through
in between a bun,
and it's amazing.
FIERI: All that meat magic
is conjured up
by French-Canadian duo Etienne
and Marian Cuerrier.
Where did you learn
about cooking the meats?
When I was a kid,
we had a cottage.
We did a lot of fishing,
hunting, foraging.
And then I went
to culinary school.
And when they opened up shop
inside an old office building,
it didn't take long
for the locals to take notice.
MAN:
It's kind of one of those really
magical hole-in-the-wall spots.
It's some of the best meat
sandwiches that you will have.
Got the smoked duck
sandwich over here.
The best part about the duck
sandwich is the duck.
It's like butter.
-It's well-seasoned, well-made,
and that's what
makes it memorable.
-What are we making?
-Our house buns.
Sir Mix-a-Lot said it almost
like this, but it ain't no fun
unless you make
your buns, hon.
There you go.
That's what he's doing.
[ Laughs ]
We got our flour,
salt, starter
we've had
for eight years now.
When that starter smells
like an old bar,
you know you're
doing it right.
Some bloomed yeast.
We'll let it mix.
After it proofs overnight,
we're gonna shape them,
proof them again,
and bake them.
So now we're gonna season
our duck breasts.
Coriander seeds here,
garlic powder, dill seeds,
salt and pepper,
summer savory, juniper berries.
Dry rub this,
vacuum seal it.
How long's it gonna sit
with the dry rub?
10 days.
Time to sear.
Fat side down.
And then we'll
let it render.
Then on to the smoker.
180.
We're gonna use cherry wood
and maple.
What's the next step?
So we're making the bacon.
Of course you're gonna
make your own bacon.
Add a little bit
of garlic powder, salt,
black pepper, long pepper.
Lung pepper?
Long pepper.
Very rich
in antioxidants.
Brown sugar.
That little amount
of seasoning?
That's it.
This is gonna go, as well,
for 10 days.
Throw it on the smoker
for 10 hours.
Everything is done
on this little smoker?
Yes.
I have to call my boys
from Camp Chef
and get you a bigger one.
[ Chuckles ]
-Guy, how you doing, man?
-I'm good, buddy.
Hey, listen, I met
this chef and his wife.
I need this guy to get one
of the big stand-up smokers.
Can we hook him up?
Absolutely,
we'll hook him up.
Let's up his game.
Thank you, brother.
Guy's the best.
Next up?
Bacon cabbage slaw.
I have the butter right now
in the pan with the onions.
So, we're gonna cut that belly
into little cubes.
Get through that skin --
too tough to eat.
But it could fashion
as a bracelet.
[ Production crew laughs ]
Once that
kind of renders down,
you glaze it
with the white wine.
We put the rest of the butter
and the cabbage,
and it's just gonna
give it that rich taste.
Duck breast is done.
Slice as thin as possible.
What, you want me to get you
a slicer now, too?
I got one, I got one.
[ Laughs ]
Warm it all up.
That same spice mix
that we rubbed it with.
We take our homemade bread,
slice it in half.
I didn't cut my hand.
[ Laughs ]
Homemade mayo.
Oh, we had to make
the mayo also
from the chickens
that we raised under the bed.
It's got lots of garlic --
almost an aioli.
Throw that on there.
Top it off
with the cabbage slaw.
And we stab it
with our knife
People will want
to cut it in half.
You got to be kidding me.
♪♪
Remember when you were
a little kid
going to
the ice cream parlor?
You get an ice cream,
and you'd take
that first bite of it,
and you're like,
"Oh, my gosh, this is so good.
I don't want to eat it
too fast, though.
It's gonna be all done."
That's what I'm having
with this sandwich
right now.
Brother, I'm gonna be
honest with you.
That changes
the world of duck.
The seasoning's awesome,
the searing and the smoking,
the thin slicing
and just the quick reheat,
the house-made bread.
I mean, the package deal --
it's outstanding.
I mean, like,
shut the front door,
the back door, the side door,
and all the windows.
[ Imitates explosion ]
Smoked duck for table eight.
Let's talk about
the duck.
It's not like any duck
you've ever tried before.
That slaw bite's a nice,
kind of salty contrast.
The bread itself
is amazing.
You hang out at cool places,
you meet cool people.
I have the mayor and the film
commissioner of Ottawa.
You guys have got
a food scene going on.
We have 1,200 farms
that surround the city,
so restaurants can go
and get local produce
15 minutes from here.
And Meat Press,
this is pretty out of bounds.
I would definitely recommend it
to a lot of people.
WOMAN:
Once you find this place,
most people come here
a couple times a week.
If this is the beginning,
what do we have coming up next?
I don't know.
Don't go anywhere.
Seriously, like,
stand right here.
They're gonna come back, and you
better make something awesome.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out here
in Ottawa, Canada.
We're at a funky joint
called Meat Press.
Now, the chef is making cured,
smoked meat --
just about everything.
Reuben ready.
The focus is on the meat.
It's the hero of the show.
Favorite thing on the menu?
The Jefferson is really good.
MAN: You got pork belly,
pulled pork,
and then you got
some capicola, also.
MAN: They fill
the sandwich up.
It's really,
really savory.
We're gonna start
by making capicola.
Hot, smoked,
spiced capicola.
Yes.
Take a capicola muscle,
salt it,
and then we're gonna put
some fermented habanero.
So we just took habanero,
salted it for six days,
and then we blended it
into this paste.
How spicy is that?
Very spicy.
I forgot
you're from Canada.
[ Laughs ]
Kashmiri
and pasilla peppers.
Smells incredible.
Now into
the vacuum seal again.
Let me guess how many days.
10 days.
Yes, it is.
See?
[ Laughs ]
It's gonna go
in the smoker
until the internal temperature
is at 150.
What else is coming
on the Jefferson?
Pulled pork shoulder.
So we're gonna put some salt,
black pepper,
long pepper,
green pepper, red pepper.
And what is
this concoction?
So this is maple syrup.
Drizzle it right on.
And this will get
vacuum sealed
and smoke it low temperature
for five hours.
Alright, we got
our smoked pork butt out.
We have the juices from the
vacuum sealed bag that we kept.
And then this is
an apple cider vinegar.
Local apple cider.
Fermented habaneros,
garlic cloves,
and we're gonna crush
in tomatoes.
Braise it 300 Fahrenheit.
Preserve the jus,
and we're gonna finish it off
into a barbecue sauce.
I like the way you roll.
Oil, onions,
pork shoulder juice,
and we're gonna add
the store-bought barbecue.
What's gonna happen next?
A confit pork belly.
How do you spell "overachiever"
in French?
"Meat Press"?
Yeah.
We just put salt, garlic,
rosemary, and vacuum seal.
Six days, this one.
Oh, really.
It's 'cause
we're running out of space
in the cooler,
just so you know.
And then we're gonna
confit it in duck fat.
350 for 2 1/2 half hours.
Press it, slice it,
and sear them up in the pan.
I don't know where you
find the time.
So first we're gonna
slice the capicola,
warm it up,
flip our pork belly.
Homemade bun,
basic slaw --
it's got oregano,
vinegar,
garlic scape,
and rosemary.
Oh, yeah, just
your regular slaw.
Pickles, capicola,
pulled pork,
seared pork belly.
I will not be
walking after this.
Drizzle a little bit of that
barbecue sauce that we made.
Close it up.
Pull it all together.
That's a butcher's rainbow
in Flavortown.
♪♪
It's outrageous.
The capicola
is the hit for me.
Nice spice out of it.
Pulled pork's super juicy.
I think the smoking/braising
is an awesome way to go.
The bacon, of course,
is another level.
I'm seriously
gonna tap out, bro.
This is, like,
turning into a whole issue.
We do a lot of takeout
containers.
You think?
[ Laughing ] Yeah.
Jefferson for table 18.
MAN:
Right from the first bite,
you can tell the difference
between all three meats.
Everything comes together
to build this big,
meaty mountain of goodness.
Just spicing up the thyme.
This is crème de la crème.
I'm always thinking
about the sandwiches.
FIERI: People are so lucky
to have you.
I have a lot of duck
in my freezer,
and I'm gonna make you
come to California real soon.
[ Laughs ]
Excellent job.
FIERI: Up next,
in Burlington, Vermont...
Go!
a cider house pouring drinks
into dishes...
Well, that I got to try.
...like wings gone wild...
This wing sauce
is outrageous.
...and a different dive
into the dip.
And that right there --
all day long.
♪♪
So you folks ask me
all the time,
"Guy, how'd you end up picking
that place for 'Triple D'?"
I got a good one for you.
The other day,
I'm in this old garage,
and in the old garage
is an old fridge.
And I open it up, and there's
some random beers and a cider --
not a regular cider,
a hard cider.
So I crack it, I take a sip,
and I'm like, "Whoa!
I haven't had one of these
in years."
And that reminds me --
in Burlington, Vermont,
there's some dudes that are
making some killer hard ciders.
Maybe it's a message
from the Flavortown universe.
This is Citizen Cider.
WOMAN: We started coming here
for the cider,
but the food
has always been fantastic.
Zucchini beet burger
in the window.
They use the ciders
in the food.
Deglaze them
with the bRosé now.
It adds a subtle sweetness,
a nice fruitiness to a dish.
FIERI: But before that sweet
and savory mash-up,
Bryan Holmes,
Justin Heilenbach,
and Kris Nelson went from
making cider in a basement
to their own facility
and restaurant.
And chef Ryan Hickey's on board
bringing it all together.
So they make cider,
and you come up with recipes.
Yes. Yes.
The cider goes in
all the food.
Oh, that's got to be my kind
of team right there, huh?
Fiery Apple wings
going down.
I think about the wings
all the time.
Kind of the perfect balance
of crunch and sauce.
Should we just start
drinking these now,
or are
they gonna actually go in?
That's this cider.
Our Dirty Mayor cider.
Dirty Mayor?
It's a ginger-infused
cider.
Tell me that's not
my cider --
the Dirty Mayor
of Flavortown.
So, we're making
Fiery Apple wings,
and this is sweet,
sparkling cider.
So that has
more sugar in it?
Yep.
Next?
A sachet
of black peppercorns,
juniper berries, tarragon.
And bay leaf.
Say, "Hey, sachet."
Water and cider vinegar.
How long's this
gonna brine?
Two days.
Then what takes place?
We toss them
in our house wing rub.
Paprika, salt,
garlic powder,
onion powder...
Okay.
...cayenne pepper,
ground black pepper.
Wings are dry-rubbed.
Bake in an oven
at 350 degrees
for 15 to 20 minutes.
Then you go to the fryer,
and what kind of sauce are we
making to serve these with?
Fiery Apple wing sauce.
Well, that I got to try.
We start with hot sauce,
Dirty Mayor,
and then we take raw apple
cider juice and boil it down.
This is the key.
Onion powder.
Cayenne and garlic?
You guessed it, sir.
This cooks down
for 25 minutes,
and then we emulsify it
with butter.
Do we give any sauce
with this?
Ranch.
Let's get into it, buddy.
Yeah.
I heard you like
to jiggle some mayonnaise.
Is that true?
Who says that
to somebody?
[ Laughs ]
Okay, I'm sorry,
creepy person.
When did this become
a thing to do?
Poking holes in the bottom
sucks it all out.
Here you go.
Keep that as a souvenir, kids.
Buttermilk, sour cream --
thank you.
Where's your fancy trick
with that one, huh?
Dried parsley,
cayenne pepper,
garlic powder,
black pepper...
ACV?
Yes, sir.
...apple cider vinegar,
onion powder...
Oregano.
...coriander, and dill.
Doctor.
You making a campfire?
Get after that.
Trying not to splatter
it everywhere.
Alright, so put it
all together.
Here's our house-made
buttermilk ranch.
This is our Fiery Apple
wing sauce that we made earlier.
Me likey wingy.
Let the games begin.
♪♪
This wing sauce
is outrageous.
Get a little heat,
get a little vinegar,
but you get a nice
little sweet.
I mean, not sweet
as in the sense, like...
...sugary sweet,
but a natural
sweetness to it.
And the meat itself has
a little bit of a sweet flavor.
I don't think I've had many
wing sauces like that.
The only thing I'm missing
is a Dirty Mayor.
[ Chuckles ]
Fiery Apple wings
in the window.
MAN:
The wings are really crispy.
The inside's really juicy.
Little hot, little sweet.
-Absolutely delicious.
When you tell people
about this place, how
do you describe it?
Best cider in the world.
FIERI: Which they're making here
and selling up
and down the East Coast.
What is bRosé?
It's rosé made by bros.
It's a cider co-fermented
with blueberries.
I want some bRosé.
You do.
Everything that comes out
of the kitchen is really good.
The lamb French dip.
The lamb French dip
is incredible.
With the lamb and
the mushrooms and onions,
it just all
fits together nicely.
I love it.
Now we're into...
Lamb French dip.
Alright, go.
Mint, black pepper,
kosher salt,
cumin, paprika, rosemary.
We try and get as local
a lamb as you can.
Vermont lamb is, like, some
of the best lamb in the world.
Just gonna go straight
to the sear.
What are we gonna
braise this in?
I imagine cider.
Tulsi cider.
It's a holy basil cider.
Go!
Nice cider facial.
Yeah.
Into the pan
and in the oven.
What temp
we cooking it to?
Medium-rare.
Now what are we into?
We got some portobellos
that we're gonna marinate.
Olive oil,
red wine vinegar...
Lemon juice.
...and soy sauce.
These are gonna marinate
how long?
Overnight.
Then they go to the grill.
Yep.
In the meantime,
the onions?
We oil nothing?
Not to start.
We just let
the sugars come out.
Sweat 'em, almost.
We'll add
the Tulsi and bourbon
and let them cook down
for another 25 minutes.
The slicer's out.
Must be time to eat.
We're gonna throw
the mushrooms and onions
right on the flat top,
and then
we're gonna cut this.
Thin to win.
Heat up some of the jus
we have leftover
from cooking the mushrooms,
warm the lamb up in it.
put it right
on the ciabatta roll,
take our mushroom
and onion mixture,
give a nice horseradish
mustard sauce,
and then our jus.
Alright, Chef, let me take
a look at this bad boy.
♪♪
The lamb is outstanding.
Nice, rich, medium rare.
Super, super tender --
as thin as he sliced it.
And then you get a little bit
of meatiness of that mushroom.
Great roll for it --
just soaks up the jus --
and then the cider kiss.
Mmm.
Really like your
onion technique.
In today's world,
we don't find
enough lamb sandwiches.
And that right there --
all day long.
Great sandwich.
Lamb French dip
in the window.
The lamb dip is awesome.
The marinated mushrooms
in it are excellent.
Very thinly sliced lamb,
perfect with the bread.
The jus is fantastic.
This place is definitely
the spot
you want to come
right after work.
Why can't you have hard cider
right before you go to work?
It would be awesome,
wouldn't it?
[ Drunkenly ] We're making
deals down here
at Charlie's Car Barn.
-The chicken banh mi.
-I really like Citizen Cider.
I come here all the time.
They're constantly
pushing the bar.
The way you're using
your cider --
using it in the sauces,
using it for all the
different aspects --
it's not an easy task,
but you're conquering it.
It's fun.
Well done, man.
FIERI: Coming up, a funky spot
in Richmond, Virginia...
Okay, they're serious.
They are crazy.
...mashing up your
not-your-everyday combo.
There's a lot of taco joints.
There's a lot
of soul food joints.
I don't think I've seen
many soul food
taco joints.
[ Glugging ]
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Richmond, Virginia,
in an area
known as Jackson Ward.
Now, I have shopped
some soul food restaurants
in my day and some taco joints,
but this might be the first time
where I've seen the two
come together.
The only question I have is,
"How'd they come up
with the name?"
This is Soul Taco.
MAN: Looking good,
looking good.
The food at this restaurant
is awesome.
Chicken Tinga Jambalaya,
Cornmeal Crusted Catfish.
It's like a fusion of soul
and Mexican food.
WOMAN:
It's a great mix together.
I think you kind of see that
from your owners, as well --
is a mix of people bringing
together really good ideas.
FIERI: That mix of pals
is Trey Owens,
Nar Hovnanian,
and Ari Augenbaum,
who add up to a unique
blend of Southern, East,
and West Coast roots.
You're the chef.
Yes.
I am operations.
Operations.
And you are?
I do marketing.
Who's bringing me
the Southern side?
Right here.
My granny was my babysitter,
and she cooked
straight-up soul cooking.
What kind of taco
are we getting?
Root beer Braised Oxtail
"al Pastor".
It's kind of an ode
to where Trey and I met.
We were working under
a chef named Chef John
who passed away,
and one of his signature dishes
had a root beer glaze on it.
Alright, I dig it.
The braised oxtail taco
is amazing.
It has pineapple and
a little bit of a hot sauce.
It's just packed full
of flavor.
FIERI: Alright,
let's get into it.
We're gonna start with
a whole oxtail right here,
a little all-purpose flour,
some salt,
a little bit of pepper,
some garlic powder,
and some chili powder,
and rub this
into the oxtail.
One big taco.
Oh, yeah.
Sear it in a little
bit of butter.
Not something you see every day,
is a big oxtail on a flat top.
Couple minutes
on each side.
I'm sorry --
Your marketing team
has attacked
the back of your head?
Yeah, you know,
I figured
I wanted something
special for you.
Let me just see.
Okay, they're serious.
They are crazy.
Now what are we gonna
braise this in?
Ox stock and root beer.
That's it?
Well, it's gonna have
a little bit of a mirepoix
in there, as well.
Okay.
So mirepoix, ox stock,
root beer, and...
And garlic and that's it.
So is it it finally?
Is it it?
That's it.
Ox stock, root beer,
mirepoix, and garlic.
Just checking.
Final answer?
Final answer.
No more ingredients?
No more ingredients.
Except for
the hidden ingredient.
I knew it!
Cover that.
It'll braise low and slow
for about 12 to 16 hours.
Next up?
Pineapple and roasted
jalapeño salsa.
Okay.
Got the pineapple,
which is gonna go
into the traditional
al pastor flavoring.
Little bit of red onion
in there, roasted jalapeños,
and some fresh
diced garlic.
Then we're gonna add
some cilantro,
squeeze a lime on there,
a little bit
of salt and pepper,
and let that just sit there
for a couple minutes
and get those flavors
in there.
And where we getting
the tortillas
and all that from?
Unfortunately,
we're buying those.
The kitchen's just
a little too small.
Unfortunately?
We would like
to be making them.
It's too small.
You got tons of room.
Don't give me that.
[ Laughs ]
Over here, there's a whole
tortilla station right here.
There could be somebody there
making tortillas all the time.
This is our oxtail
that's been slow-cooking.
It's got the nice
dark caramelization
that we have on there,
but once you get in there,
you can see
all of the juicy meat
that just sits
right underneath.
Okay.
We're just gonna put a couple
of tortillas on the flat top.
A little bit of oil
on the grill,
a little bit
of that oxtail,
and this is
our root beer glaze.
Chop it up
just a little bit.
A little bit of pineapple
jalapeño salsa;
nice, crispy, puffed up
chicharrones;
and a little bit
of our agave hot sauce.
We're good to go.
What's in it?
We just take hot sauce,
blend it with
100% pure agave.
Okay.
♪♪
The first thing you get
is just the sweet of the meat --
the richness of the oxtail
and the reduced root beer.
Then I got a little bit
of the agave chili.
Now a little pineapple.
This is the zinger,
though.
Got a spoon for you,
if you want.
No, I'll just chug it
right off the bottle.
Absolutely.
Let's do shots.
I take it right in.
When you're putting soul food
and tacos together,
when you're making
this funky fusion,
it's gonna be a little bit
alarming at the beginning,
but stick with it.
You'll dig it.
Really good taco.
Thank you.
I'm glad you enjoy it.
Good braise on the meat.
Thank you.
Our root beer braised oxtail.
WOMAN: It is delicious.
It has, like, a little bit
of heat to it,
and then the pineapple
added with that sweetness.
You've got all this,
like, sort of umami
because they combine sweet
and savory and salty
all at the same time.
Whole lot of love
and a little bit of soul.
Great food.
It's different
than any other taco
or any other place here.
I think it really adds a whole
new kind of vibe to the area.
WOMAN: They've chosen
to build up local artists
then just having events
and collaborating
with the community.
-Which has caught the attention
of some big hitters.
Mayor, so tell me.
Give me the rundown on Richmond.
STONEY: It's a deeply
historic city.
We got new-school
and old-school.
I like to say also we got great
restaurants, like Soul Taco.
The tacos are great,
and the soul food's great,
as well.
That's why
he's the mayor.
[ Chuckles ]
That smells like happiness
right there, guys.
MAN: Oh, yeah.
This place is phenomenal.
I'd come here every day
if my wife let me.
FIERI: There's a lot
of taco joints.
There's a lot of soul
food joints.
I don't think I've seen
many soul food taco joints.
Got to be first.
Well done.
Thank you.
So was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry --
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this county.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
♪♪
But I just want to...
[ Laughter ]