You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D' -- How'd they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
Living on the edge,
these two.
...a Kansas City barbecue spot
smoking serious meat...
I'd risk life and limb
for some more of that.
...blowing up their building
and earning all the awards.
I would wear the banner
as a cape.
In Dallas, Texas...
You talking to me?
Talkin' to me?
...a neighborhood joint
putting a spin on Tex-Mex.
Mmm! Oh, my gosh,
that's outstanding.
And a D.C. destination...
My boy Tow Truck here.
...taking subs to
a whole nother level.
Flavortown overload.
Familiar faces,
new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Love coming to Kansas City.
I mean, you want to talk about
some of the best barbecue
in the world,
you'll find it in this city.
Now, I believe that it was
about 2010
I came to check this joint out.
Husband-and-wife team
won all the major competitions.
I mean, they rock it.
And they got a funky place
where they serve up
some bomb burnt ends.
Wow, looks like things
have changed a little bit.
But I know the barbecue hasn't.
This is Smokin' Guns BBQ.
Pork belly bites coming up.
Man:
After I saw it on "Triple D,"
I came down, I had it.
It was even better
than it looked on TV.
Smokin' Guns is sort of
an institution in Kansas City.
Quality barbecue every time.
FIERI: That's 'cause Smokin' Gun
owners Phil and Linda Hopkins,
well, they know a thing or two
about medal-making barbecue.
The biggest one we've won
is actually
the Jack Daniel's in 1999.
The world championship.
Let's just take a moment.
That's the big one.
I mean,
I would have the trophy
screw-gunned
to the front of my truck,
and I would wear
the banner as a cape.
I mean, that's --
that's huge, brother.
And that championship style
is still part
of every plate
that flies off the line.
You still competing?
-Yep.
-Yes.
Six to eight times a year,
just stay local.
Just try
to keep it easy.
You know, just
mild competitions.
I've been to barbecue
competitions.
I've seen you win.
Everybody wants to know
what's the secret.
I think a lot
of it's in the rub.
FIERI: The rub that we're gonna
make right now --
I mean, has this been
the go-to rub the entire time?
Yes, this is the exact recipe
we won the Jack Daniel's with.
Tell us what it is.
Salt, sugar, brown sugar...
Now, wait a second.
This isn't just
regular brown sugar.
It's brown sugar that's been
dried in the oven
and put in a food processor.
So, now it's more of a powder
with a little granule in it.
Aha!
That's like CIA barbecue
right there.
Paprika, chili powder,
cumin, white pepper,
some black pepper...
A little Cayenne.
...Cayenne, garlic powder,
onion powder, a little Accent --
it's a flavor enhancer.
And then I'm gonna let you know
what the two
that nobody
has ever guessed in 10 years.
The two ingredients
that no one's ever guessed.
Cinnamon and clove?
You were right on with that one.
That one's cinnamon.
Thank you.
Now, this is...
Cocoa.
You're gonna tell me
that that amount of cocoa
gonna make a difference?
Wait until you taste it.
The rub I made
on the old show --
We sold 54,000 pounds
of that last year.
27 tons.
All right, so let's grab
one of those briskets.
What size are we gonna use?
Around 16.
Wow.
I'm gonna trim it
real lightly --
skim fat off of it --
just so I can get some seasoning
down to that meat.
You see him run that knife
like a surgeon?
Gonna apply some of this rub.
Okay, let's go.
Now, what we have here...
How long you had this?
Eight years.
Got your money out of this,
didn't you?
I still have that cooker
in the museum
over at the warehouse.
Yeah, I was just gonna say
there's got to be
a museum
of Smokin' Guns.
Okay, brisket goes down --
225?
9 to 11 hours.
All right, now as long as
I've been doing barbecue,
one guy that's been kind of
like a mentor,
one dude that I've always
been able to look at,
ask the good barbecue questions
to -- "Dr. BBQ" Ray Lampe.
I'm always happy to come out
and test some barbecue.
I know you are.
We knew Dr. BBQ
from competing against him.
It was just really fun
for him to be here.
He's a good dude.
-Look at that.
-Beautiful.
Man, that's what
it's supposed to look like.
Now we're gonna
let it rest.
How long?
15 minutes.
15 "I want to pick at it
and eat some of it" minutes.
All right.
Now skim off any fat thicker
than a quarter of an inch.
Very nice.
How thick you like yours?
Pencil-thick, just like
I was at a contest.
Now, Ray, I'm under
the impression
that you should be able
to pull it lightly,
it should come apart.
Exactly.
Stretchiness,
that's what you want,
but it has to come apart.
Okay.
Put it on the sandwich.
Nice, not dry,
beautiful.
That rub, dude.
Fantastic.
I'd risk life and limb
for some more of that.
MAN:
Got a brisket sandwich.
There's all kinds of great
barbecue joints around,
but the burnt ends
are still something
that I remember to this day
being one of my favorites.
Here we have
the burnt end,
now it was back on the smoker
for four hours
after we skimmed the fat off
and re-seasoned it.
So, what we're gonna do now
is cut it into chunks.
Oh, baby.
Took this right out
of the center.
Tears apart like
the thin slices did.
Holy moly!
I've had some burnt ends
in my day.
They up there
somewhere?
Gotta be
in my top three.
Alright!
Top three.
Made my day.
So, what are
the highlights here?
What do we got?
Smoked meat loaf.
Was this on the menu
when I came here last time?
Oh, no,
it's completely new.
This is new?
Yeah, it's our version
of barbecue comfort food.
Barbecue
is comfort food!
[ Laughs ]
Yes, it is!
What are the meats
in there?
We use two parts
choice or higher brisket,
one part pork
that we grind ourself, in house.
We use
our own meat loaf seasoning.
It's dried mustard, paprika,
a little salt, thyme,
basil, black pepper,
onion powder,
garlic powder,
and some breadcrumbs.
And instead of the traditional
tomato sauce,
we put barbecue sauce
in it.
Living on the edge,
these two.
We add eggs,
mix it all together,
put it in the pan,
put it on the smoker.
How long
does this go down for?
About four hours.
It's been one of
our best sellers so far.
Like that smoke ring
on that.
Delicious.
Not dry.
Super tender.
That's good meat loaf.
Mmm.
SERVER:
Here's your smoked meat loaf.
The meat loaf has got
a really good texture.
The pork and the brisket
meld together
to where it gives it
a good full flavor.
It's got a good
mild smoky flavor.
It doesn't overpower you.
MAN:
Really good.
God, that's so good!
I want to eat so much more!
I'm gonna go into a food coma!
[ Snores ]
But there's no time for sleep,
'cause coming up...
We still got turkey.
Oh, God help.
...the kitchen's
getting rough.
Ooh!
Just pull it out!
But I still can't get enough.
That's dangerous,
what that is.
FIERI:
I'm back in Kansas City
at a joint
I first visited in 2010.
Aah!
And this place is legendary.
I mean, we're talking over 14
years of competition barbecue,
over 400 awards,
and one killer brisket.
This is Smokin' Guns BBQ.
But these days,
things look a little different.
SERVER:
Pulled pork nachos.
Are we on
the same property?
You know,
our original restaurant
was located right next door.
When we decided we needed
a bigger place,
we had this building built.
We went from 1,800 square feet
to 12,000.
And then once this got done,
you tore it down and paved it.
Yep.
Yep, we kept this.
You cut that out
of the old wall?
Yes, I did.
Wow!
It's kind of neat to see
what it was to what it is now.
And their great food has
just brought them a long way.
What pterodactyl poultry
is that?
Whole tom turkey breast,
skin on.
Comes in frozen.
It's thawed out enough
that we can apply the rub
and it'll stick to it.
Why aren't we gonna thaw it
out all the way?
So I can put it on at night
and let it cook all night
and not have to get up
before 3:00 in the morning.
Really?!
Yes.
A science to it.
Okay. We're gonna
apply rub all over this,
just like we did
the brisket.
That's it?
That's it.
No brining?
No brining.
Poultry loves
to be brined.
That's true, if you have
a problem
keeping it moist through
the cooking process.
Ohh!
[ Laughs ]
I'm sorry.
That hurt?
Just pull it out!
Aah!
Okay, on to the smoker.
Right.
How long
is this gonna go on?
10 to 12 hours, 225.
Semi-frozen.
Mm! Alright, let's go.
I'm starving.
That's not dry at all.
Look at the bark
on the outside.
That's not skin, folks.
We're actually gonna
add some au jus
to these pieces, too.
You can't make it any better,
can you?
Oh, yeah.
And I'm gonna add a little rub
to the au jus,
squeeze all the juice
we can out of that skin.
Stir that up, let it run
right over it and soak right in.
That's a whole nother layer
of flavor.
Ohh.
It's outstanding.
I'm gonna have to slow it down
after having
another bite
of the turkey.
What's my next try?
I call these
Christian's Piggy Backs,
after one of my grandsons.
It's made out of whole
pork bellies.
Rub it with the rub --
same rub we used to --
Right.
Smoke it for three to four
hours, cut it up into chunks.
When you order it,
we deep-fry it,
and then we put more rub on it
right out of the deep fryer,
serve it
with our sweet sauce.
Now, I don't want to correct you
on this, captain,
being the fact
that you've won
every competition
under the sun,
but basically,
what you're giving me
is a pork belly burnt end.
Yeah, that's basically
what it is.
♪♪
That's dangerous,
what that is.
They're very good.
Delicious.
Really dynamite.
MAN: They're small, so you just
pop them in your mouth.
Very juicy, very flavorful.
It's crispy on the outside
and good bacon flavor.
Who doesn't love bacon?
COOK:
Pork belly bite for the bar.
You've stayed the same way.
You're doing the same thing.
You're making
the great food.
Now you're just offering it
to a bigger audience.
You've done it my friend.
Congratulations.
You deserve it.
Wow!
Their new barbecue emporium --
massive.
They went from 48 seats
to 450 seats,
plus they still
find time to compete.
Now, up next in Dallas,
a chef twisted
a true Texas tradition...
People in this area call it
"Tex-Mex."
...putting the emphasis
on his own ethnic eats.
You say no. You're...
Mex-Tex.
That soup is gangster.
Mmm!
FIERI: Tex-Mex joints
are a dime a dozen
in the Lone Star state,
but Mex-Tex?
Well, that's one
I had to try.
So, back in 2012, I hit up
this place in Dallas
for an authentic spin
on the old standby.
This is Pepe's & Mito's
Mexican Café.
♪♪
WOMAN: After seeing
the "Triple D" episode,
I had to come and try it.
SERVER:
Enjoy, guys.
I'm addicted to it now.
MAN: I've been coming here
for more than two decades.
I know Pedro really well.
He's an artist with his food.
FIERI:
He's talking about Pedro Rojas,
who's flipping the script
on a regional favorite.
People in this area call it
"Tex-Mex."
You say no. You're...
Mex-Tex.
I come from Mexico.
Our Mexican influence
is always first.
Alright,
what are we making?
Caldo albondigas.
Caldo...
Albondigas.
...albondigas.
The meatball soup.
Okay?
Okay, we're gonna start
with a little canola oil,
chopped onions.
Bell peppers, tomatoes.
We got some minced garlic,
black pepper, ground cumin --
cumino.
Water.
Let it sit
for about 20 minutes.
We got some chicken base
in there.
Bring it to a boil.
Add some fresh cilantro to it.
And simmer
for about 20 minutes.
Alright,
we're gonna make some --
He's like the Mexican
Robert De Niro.
Huh?
What do you think?
You talkin' to me?
We meet a lot of people
from out of town
and have seen us on TV,
and they always make the joke,
"Where's Robert De Niro?"
Talkin' to me?
You talkin' to me?
We're gonna make some picadillos
for the albondigas --
for the albondigas,
the meatballs.
A little bit of margarine.
We use
extra-lean ground beef.
Well, it is
swimsuit season.
Brown that for
about five minutes.
Carrots.
Potatoes, diced onions,
black pepper,
cumino, granulated garlic.
And a little salt.
Diced poblano peppers.
So that's it?
We take this,
make the meatball.
We gonna beat an egg.
And then we gonna add
the picadillo.
So, this is
all cooked together,
and that will make the abagon--
abadond-- agga-bugga --
Albondigas.
There you go.
That's Al Bundy's brother
from Guatemala.
Hey!
Oh!
This is gonna be good.
♪♪
That soup is gangster.
Mmm!
The broth is
so rich, flavorful
with the peppers
and onions and the tomatoes.
Mmm!
Dynamite.
Since "Triple D" came,
we got so busy.
COOK:
Beef fajitas up!
ROJAS:
It's been really good.
FIERI: So good that his kids
are now pitching in
to help serve up
the family favorites.
SERVER:
This is our Beef Guiso.
Beef Guiso's very popular,
very common in Mexico.
It's basically kind of
like a Mexican stew.
This is ground sirloin,
potatoes, diced onions.
Now we add ground cumin,
ground pepper,
granulated garlic, and salt.
Tomatillo sauce.
Start by adding the tomatillos,
peppers, onion, water.
And boil it
for about 10 minutes.
Blend with a little
chopped cilantro.
♪♪
Now we add homemade
tomato sauce.
And we finish it off
with chicken stock.
And now it's ready
to put on a plate.
We serve it with homemade
flour tortillas.
Beef Guiso up!
♪♪
The meat is great.
The potatoes are firm.
It's got
a little spice to it.
It's excellent.
The flavor of the sauce
is really good.
To me, it's sort of tangy.
The beef is really tender.
It all works together
really well.
Yes!
MAN: Let's go!
It was amazing for us
to experience.
We had no idea.
We've always craved
all the restaurants
he would feature on TV.
Mmm! Oh, my gosh,
that's outstanding!
But we never thought,
you know,
one day we're gonna
be on the show.
I'm so close to Mexico
and I'm in the land of Tex-Mex,
although this
is Mex-Tex.
It needs to be
the real deal.
That's the real deal.
That was on
my bucket list.
You know, it happened.
If you dream about something,
it can happen.
Well, I'm really glad
I could help you check off
something on your bucket list,
but, brother, you got there
all on your own.
Now, coming up...
Two large Bolognese.
...the secret's out
at this Washington, D.C.,
sandwich shop...
I didn't know
he could hear me.
...where the super-sized subs
need their own zip codes.
I don't know
what to do.
Just bite the top of it.
[ Growls ]
[ Laughter ]
Back in 2015, I heard about
a hard-to-find mom-and-pop shop
in the heart
of Washington, D.C.,
where the subs actually
did look like submarines,
and the folks running it
are still known
as the Hoagie Heroes
of the neighborhood.
SERVER: Hi, folks.
This is Bub and Pop's.
♪♪
I saw a sign that Guy was here,
and I just had to try it, too.
I got four Bolognese
all day.
Love it.
MAN: They have
fresh ingredients, fresh food.
So it's something
that's really enjoyable.
This is not a sub shop.
This is a really classy place.
People from
around the world,
when they come to D.C.,
they find us.
Dignitaries.
No, with him here,
we don't get dignitaries.
My boy Tow Truck here?
-Yeah.
-This guy?
I thought we were gonna go do
some collections together.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Tow Truck is actually
French-trained chef Jon Taub,
who runs this place
with his mom, Arlene,
and stepdad, Alan.
ARLENE: Seeing Jonathan
working with Guy
just swelled my heart
with pride.
This restaurant is based off
Philly soul food --
cheesesteaks, hoagies,
roast pork, brisket.
I mean, we're from Philly.
I couldn't even tell.
You couldn't tell?
No!
You're not from Arizona?
Alright, Big Jon,
what are we into now, buddy?
Okay, this is
our roast pork sandwich.
Okay, this is pork belly,
so we're into porchetta, baby.
Yes, sir.
First thing,
salt and pepper.
Ground and toasted
fennel seed.
I like the fact
that you toasted it.
All right, this is
garlic confit.
This is the juice and the zest
of one orange,
one lime, and one lemon.
Okay.
I want to get that in everywhere
on this thing.
This guy is very, very serious
about what he's doing.
Very serious.
Making sandwiches.
I didn't know
he could hear me.
Picked rosemary.
Okay.
Same thing with the thyme?
Yes, sir.
Fresh sage.
Okay.
This is my favorite part.
Pecorino Romano.
Dude, this is like
flavor explosion
over here
in hoagie heaven.
So, now we're gonna add
our pork loin,
and then we're gonna
tie the porchetta
so we can roast it off.
4 hours and 20 minutes.
Got it.
Then the next day,
we rub the skin
with really good
olive oil, salt, pepper.
And then we blast it in this
pizza oven at 600, 700 degrees.
Let it rest 30 minuets,
then we slice it down.
Broccoli rabe in there.
So you got a little bitterness
coming in there.
Yep.
That's our porchetta.
Okay.
Now we're gonna slice
that bad boy.
Look at that.
♪♪
Mmm!
Flavortown overload.
What you offer in
that porchetta sandwich
is really generous.
And I don't mean
in the portion size.
I just mean
in the effort.
I mean, it just makes you
step back for a second
and go, "Wow."
I think he was blown away by it,
and at the end of the day,
it makes you feel good
for somebody to recognize that.
And people
are also recognizing
his everything-from-scratch
Bolognese Parmesan.
This is my favorite sandwich
on the menu.
We're gonna make meatballs,
mix the milk
and the breadcrumbs together,
and this is gonna
lighten the meatballs
so they're not too heavy.
Add the ground pork,
ground beef,
Pecorino Romano cheese,
whole eggs, fresh garlic,
salt and pepper,
whole fennel seed,
and crushed red pepper.
Just mix this all up
so it's fully incorporated.
Now we're gonna ball them up
so we can bake them off.
We're gonna make
our Italian sausage.
There's a little chili flake
and a little sugar.
So it's a combination hot
and a sweet Italian sausage.
There's a little chili flake
and a little sugar.
celery, carrot,
crushed tomatoes,
and we're gonna let this cook
for about a half hour.
Then we're gonna add
carar melized onions,,
and our Italian sausage ragu,
arugula, mild provolone cheese.
It's gonna go in
a 500-degree oven
for five to six minutes.
Two large Bolognese
for table number 20!
♪♪
WOMAN: The mix of meatballs
and sausage --
everything's tender.
It's all delicious.
It all falls apart.
WOMAN #2: I don't know
how Jonathan does it,
but he really manages
to combine everything
so that one thing
compliments the other.
It's so good with
the homemade chips.
Handmade chips.
The homemade chips
are just incredible,
and the dip -- I don't even
know what's in this dip.
It's so good.
We make this French onion dip
completely from scratch.
It's a mixture of sour cream,
fresh scallions, red onion,
caramelized onions.
MAN: It's delicious.
It's homemade.
It's something you're not gonna
find at your grocery store.
It's amazing.
Why do I want to make
a movie about you
fighting through
the sandwich world
in the streets of Philly?
Fighting through the slicer
like this?
When Guy came, it was just
like a freight train.
[ Laughs ]
It just kept getting busier
and busier and busier.
-Are the shrimps ready, Rosey?
-Yeah.
TAUB: When people come in,
they ask, "What did Guy eat?"
We sell two whole porchettas
a day.
And we probably sell quadruple
the amount of our Jewish hoagie.
♪♪
I don't know what to do.
You just bite the top of it.
[ Growls ]
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
It's really great.
That's
a real tasty sandwich.
Good job, brother.
The Jewish hoagie --
We renamed it the Hebrew Hammer.
One of my brother's friends
in the military,
my brother knocked him out
in the training session.
He called him
the "Hebrew Hammer."
Where is he?
In the Air Force.
He's in the Air Force.
Overseas.
That is awesome.
Freedom ain't free,
and we're lucky to have him.
FIERI":
Sadly, Jon's brother, Pete,
died fighting for our country
just before their episode aired
in December of 2015.
Big shout-out to Pete.
Pete!
We really appreciate everything
Pete did for our country
and all the amazing members
of our armed forces.
You are a huge part
of the Flavortown army.
Just like his brother, Jon,
who's winning over
Washington, D.C.,
with as-big-as-your-head-size
hoagies,
and Pedro, who's turning
the tables on Tex-Mex in Dallas,
and barbecue legends
Phil and Linda,
who now have 10 times
the mouths to feed
at their joint
in Kansas City.
Plus, we'll be boppin'
into more places next time
on "Triple D Nation."
We don't really take off fat,
but this is what we do do.
Did you just
say "doo-doo"?
This is what we do do.
You said "doo-doo" again.
I did say it.
You said "doo-doo," Jon.
But I didn't say it quick enough
to actually be "doo-doo."
[ Laughs ]