Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
"Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives."
This trip...
We're off the rails
at this point.
We are.
...it's all about
all in the family.
To see a family
that's sticking together
in the restaurant business,
you got to be one tough,
tenacious family.
Like a mother/son tribute
in Richmond, Virginia...
Dude, you got it going.
You got it going.
...a seafood legacy
in Ottawa, Canada...
Bring on the lobster.
...and Char-B-Que
in Reno, Nevada...
That's no joke.
...fired up by a father/son
dream team.
I can talk about food
and people gain weight.
I am so stealing
that line.
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins, & Dives."
♪♪
Now, you always hear me talking
about my family on "Triple D,"
and there's something about it.
There's something
about families,
and the restaurant business,
and working together,
and the crazy dynamic,
and the awesome food.
Well, I hear
there's a place here,
south of Reno, Nevada,
that's got a great story.
It's a dad that's got
a long history
in the meat business,
his three sons, and his wife.
And what they're turning out
is something you haven't seen.
This is Butcher's Kitchen
Char-B-Que.
Order up,
brisket sandwich.
It's barbecue,
but it's way more refined.
Char that tri-tip
to perfection.
Ed Ferencik, he forgot more
about meat than I'll ever know.
He's worked in the meat business
for over 40 years.
Not my first rodeo.
Ed's son went
to culinary school.
They teamed up.
FIERI: Then father and son got
the rest of the family on board
dealing their unique meats.
Give me the spirit
of the business here,
You're not a butcher shop.
We're a Char-B-Que --
char pit and barbecue.
To see a family that's sticking
together
in the restaurant business,
you got to be one tough,
tenacious family.
I'm going to let my freak flag
fly today, Guy, so look out.
Let's go, boys.
I cut Ed's hair, and I said,
"I don't want your money.
I want your ribs."
I knew he was a gangster.
One order of rib tips.
-Meat candy.
-Yeah.
-Meat candy?
-Candy is the rib tips.
MAN: Kind of like little
popcorn chicken,
but barbecue beef,
so it's even better.
Okay, what are we
gonna do, boss?
Well, this is going to be
our house rub.
We're going to start with kosher
salt, chili powder, paprika,
brown sugar, curry powder,
black pepper, onion powder-
He's got every single thing
on the shelf.
...onion flake, garlic powder,
garlic...
-Garlic flake.
-...flake, celery seed.
Would it be easier to say
the things
that you didn't
put in here?
Stick with the script, Guy.
Marjoram, finocchio,
or better known as fennel.
Throwing
his Italian around.
Crushed red pepper, oregano,
cumin, basil,
parsley,
and a little thyme.
Thyme. All that folks,
just for you.
So this is the spare rib,
cut off of the baby back rib.
I'm told
you're a food guy.
Oh, yeah, I've cooked
a little bit in my day.
The longest bone is about
the third or fourth bone in,
that's going to start
our cut line.
That's a rib tip.
This'll get cooked
as St. Louis style ribs,
and that'll be
the rib tips.
That's right.
Three hours of smoke,
right below 200 degrees.
-What are we up to next?
We are making our house-made
barbecue sauce.
Starting with ketchup,
soy sauce...
-Worcestershire.
-...Worcestershire sauce,
apple cider vinegar,
house-made guajillo paste.
It's three different
New Mexico chilies.
-Okay.
-Pineapple chunks and juice.
You think
I didn't see that coming?
-Fish sauce.
-Didn't see that one coming.
Little bit of liquid smoke,
lemon juice, oil, garlic,
sea salt,
cumin, mustard powder,
white pepper
for that umami,
paprika, cayenne, black pepper,
and some onion powder.
Okay, hit with
the immersion blender?
That's right.
And this is the house sauce
we're putting on the rib tips?
We use some of it
in our jus that we make.
Apple juice concentrate,
apple cider vinegar,
our house-made barbecue,
cold water.
After the tips
come out of the smoker,
we jus them up,
cook them in the oven,
250 degrees,
190 to 195 cook temperature.
And then we're going to
finish them on the grill?
Then when you order them,
they go --
That's a big
overachiever.
Get a proper char on them,
chop them up,
and then put them back
on the grill to finish the char.
We put more work
into one dish
then I see some restaurants
do in all five dishes.
It's like 97 steps.
It's like the tango of barbecue.
Our customers like them.
♪♪
Wow.
Tender is an understatement.
The char --
it wrecks ribs for me.
It's like the first bite
of any rib,
only every single bite.
The sauce is ridiculous,
straight-up gangster.
Mac and cheese is great.
Whose recipe is that?
That's my son, Ed.
That's no joke. The rib tips,
they're outstanding.
I've got rib tips
coming up.
There's tons of flavor.
You pick up hints
from the smoker,
and you definitely pick up
the spice that he uses.
I got a salmon plate.
What's your favorite thing
when you come here?
I usually come
for the burrito,
but these ribs
are some of the best.
[ Whistles ]
The what?
They make burritos
on Monday.
It's not just regular barbecue.
I mean this is barbecue plus.
Yes.
You got a little bit
of everything for everyone.
Here's the deal.
We're right outside of Reno.
I'm hanging out
with a crazy man.
When we come back
we'll see what happens.
FIERI: Because he's putting
together a sandwich
that I think
could be a crazy idea.
Got a filet mignon
sandwich.
Filet mignon sandwich,
it's tenderized.
Melted cheese on top, crunchy
vegetables, just a great combo.
-See you in a bit. I want more.
-Good.
I got to find something
to do with my spare time.
I'm going to tell you
something, tape your ears on
when you get here
because he'll talk them off.
Okay. Oh.
♪♪
Welcome back, "Triple D,"
hanging outside
of Reno, Nevada,
at Butcher's Kitchen Char-B-Que.
FIERI: And the wild man here
is Big Ed...
I can talk about food
and people gain weight.
I am so stealing
that line.
...who owns the joint
with Ed Jr.
You're sort of like a Rembrandt
in the kitchen.
Plus he's pulled his other boys
into the fire.
Just the way I taught you
for the last 25 years.
The food is phenomenal.
You smell it before you
even walk in the front door.
One filet mignon sandwich.
The filet is as tender
as you can get.
There is a good char
on the meat.
Plan for a nap afterwards.
Filet mignon is of all the cuts
of meat, my least favorite.
There's not a lot of flavor.
I don't like it grilled.
So when I heard
about this on the menu,
I had to see it.
Let's get in the marinade.
Okay, red wine vinegar.
We've got some lemon juice.
That is a lot of acid.
Fresh garlic,
crushed red pepper.
He's making
Italian dressing.
Right. Black pepper, basil,
oregano, sugar.
We've got some parsley,
mustard powder.
-Okay.
-A little bit of thyme.
And we got our salt.
Give this a good blend.
We're going to add
a little bit of water,
so it all comes
together well.
Add in our olive oil. We want
to give it some mouthfeel.
You should really think
about going on
the Food Network
or something.
You know,
I got some ideas.
We wouldn't even have time
to break for commercial.
Now you're bringing this
mo-tender.
This is a tool that I created.
It's called The Impressor.
It's 60 razorblades,
spring loaded.
I tried to give you one
at The Truckee Diner.
FIERI: Which is a "Triple D"
joint we visited 10 years ago,
where Big Ed happened
to be eating.
Well, I couldn't take it,
I can't fly with that.
It's going to cut through
the connective tissue,
the things that make meat tough.
-Right.
But it's also great for fast
marinating and brining.
Why don't we turn this
into an infomercial?
A picture speaks
a thousand words.
This comes with
two pounding plates,
just broadening it out
a little bit.
I like what you're talking
about, boss.
So, now how long is the marinade
going to sit on here?
Two to four hours -- that
thing's flavored to the core.
Then we're going to cook it
to a medium-rare,
cover it with provolone.
Put it on a toasted bun
with peppers and onions,
and pepperoncinis.
It's pretty simple,
but knowing this guy,
it's not going to be
simple on the flavor.
[ Clock ticking ]
[ Bell dings ]
Yep. I was able to
make it happen, folks.
I kept him from the talking
for one whole minute.
One whole.
I beat the family world record.
You win the prize.
All right, back
to my old statement.
I'm not a fan of the filet,
but if you're going to give it
that kiss of the vinegar
and the garlic,
and then you hit it
with the acid,
and the sweetness of the
caramelized onions and peppers,
but then you get some of
the cherry peppers in there,
and a little
salty provolone.
Yeah.
This is what you want
in a steak sandwich.
The real deal.
-Thank you.
What do you think of the filet
mignon sandwich?
It's fantastic.
You get the smoke,
you get the herbs.
I'm devouring it.
It's delicious.
Bratwurst sandwich.
MAN: The family really loves
what they do
and it comes out in the food.
-Super impressed.
-Thank you.
-Speaking of presses.
[ Laughter ]
Available.
Up next, a Richmond,
Virginia, spot doing it all...
You're an animal.
...from breakfast baking
to dynamite dinner...
You are the center city
type deli
that everybody wants
to have in their town.
...all in the name of pop.
Your pops has got to be
super proud, man.
♪♪
I'm here at City Center,
Richmond, Virginia.
Now, every major city
has got a downtown like this,
and what will you find there?
Well, most likely a deli.
You know the one, you go there,
you get your coffee
and your muffin?
But with me and "Triple D,"
I want it handmade.
I want it scratch-made.
I want that family feel,
and I hear this
is just the joint.
Pop's Market On Grace.
Walking in,
we got Cuban, Reuben.
We love Pops, very flavorful.
Scrambles getting hot.
You can find the classics here.
You can find new things here.
Seared scallop
with saffron risotto.
You could literally come here
and eat three meals every day.
FIERI: That's because this is
no one-hit wonder.
Josh Wright and his mom, Patti,
are doing some serious
multitasking with
a family touch.
I know the restaurant's
named after your dad.
My dad. Her dad.
Both pops.
We saw a need for the deli,
a bakery, and dinner, as well.
Hanger steak, gnocchi hash.
The hanger steak's
really popular.
The gnocchi's like
little pillows of heaven.
A bang for your buck,
you're getting a good deal.
What is the dish
that we're making here?
It's the gnocchi with?
-Hanger steak.
-All right, let's go.
Gonna rice these potatoes.
You want to get
really light,
fluffy mashed potatoes
for gnocchi.
This is the way to do it.
-With some whole eggs.
I'll salt it. Flour.
And as little as he can
mess with this, the better.
Gorgeous.
And I'm doing about
the top side of your pinky.
When I tell you light
and delicate,
barely holding together.
We drop these
in the salted water.
Two to three minutes
until they float.
What are we on to?
This is gonna be
the sauce for the steak.
Red wine.
-Some demi paste.
-Balsamic and honey.
-Reduce.
Finish the sauce
with some butter.
All right, chef,
let's get into it.
This is
a roasted garlic oil.
That pan's smoking.
Salt and pepper.
-Please.
-Nice little hanger steak.
We're gonna go in
with the gnocchi.
And you're giving it
a hard sear,
and it just melts,
it's pillowy on the inside.
Creminis and some medium white,
shallot, a little garlic.
And now we're going
to the broil.
Good colors.
Add some arugula.
What time
do you get here?
6:30 in the morning.
What time do you leave?
-10:30 at night.
-You're an animal.
We got our sauce, the gnocchi,
slice up the steak,
it can go right on top of that.
A little olive oil.
For a lot of families,
this looks more like
a Thanksgiving Day
platter.
Here at Pop's though,
they just call it one meal.
♪♪
That was dangerous. I'm glad
I don't live in this town.
That's how I like
my gnocchi done.
When it's just boiled, it's
like missing the next chapter.
-Yeah.
-See that sear?
This is definitely nap food,
but I'm going to tell you what,
this is outstanding.
Well done, brother.
-Thank you, sir.
-Well done.
Gnocchis
are hitting the plate.
Hanger steak is always
perfectly cooked.
WOMAN: The sauce on it
is a little tangy,
unlike any kind of
hanger steak that I've had.
How do you describe
this place to people?
I mean, it's just
really elevated.
-It has everything.
-Fresh bread, fresh desserts.
WOMAN: I come here every morning
for coffee and a bagel.
For lunch, just to get
their sandwiches.
Walking in,
we've got a banh mi.
Banh mi sandwich is terrific.
MAN: Bread is house made,
it's delicious.
It's got really good spice
in the pork.
It makes a mess,
which is always a sign
of a great sandwich, right?
All right.
What are we going to do?
We're making our chicken
liver pâté now.
-Okay, good talk.
-Yep.
Let's have a very clear
understanding.
I am not a big fan of the parts
of the animal that had a job.
Okay.
Chicken liver pâté
does have its place,
but it has to be done right,
so not to be nervous.
Cured chicken livers.
Shallots, a little garlic,
allspice.
Coriander and fennel,
white pepper, cayenne pepper,
and a little bit of ginger,
and I'm going
to grate some nutmeg.
Let's go with some
sherry, cream.
And that's going to go
to the food processor.
We're off to the races.
And now we're going to
emulsify it with butter.
And we're looking
for a sound really.
FIERI: Only here,
at Pop's Market On Grace,
can you look for a sound.
I'm looking for
that sound right now.
-It's lapping.
-There.
-That's what you're looking for.
-There you go.
We're going to make
our Cuban bread here,
so we've got some starter,
salt, yeast,
vegetable shortening,
AP flour, and water.
How many different types
of breads and rolls
and muffins and shenanigans
do you guys make?
There's two different bagels,
the English, the biscuits,
the focaccia bread, banana
nut bread in the mornings.
It's a half-hour show.
Yeah, sorry.
Yeah, yeah,
87 breads.
We'll let it proof, bake it off,
and we'll have our Cuban bread.
We're into pork butts
for this banh mi.
Yep. We're going to rub the pork
with salt, thyme's coming in.
-And garlic.
-Just a little bit of water.
-Foil wrap.
-Yup.
Roast this off.
And braise them
for six hours.
Now we're ready
to build our banh mi.
So we have some
reserve pork.
-Okay.
-We're gonna refry this pork,
almost like
a fried chicken style.
This just in.
He's not your friend.
A homemade chili glaze.
This dude don't stop.
Chopped cilantro
and scallion.
A lot of work
for one sandwich, buddy.
Let's see if it's all worth it.
We're going to hinge this.
-Mmm!
-That's a little hibachi sauce.
It is a garlic mayonnaise, which
I think was more traditional.
Okay.
But we went ahead
with some ginger and ketchup.
We're off the rails
at this point.
We are. Pâté.
-There you go.
-These are house-pickled.
-Okay.
-So this is red onion.
Carrots on the top.
Cucumber and red radish.
And last thing
we're waiting for?
Chili glazed pork.
Well, it's a monster.
You've scratched made about
every single thing on this.
♪♪
This thing is more
sophisticated and balanced...
it kind of wrecks it for me
with other banh mis now.
The twice-cooked pork,
the crunch,
there's little heat
in this.
The pâté is delicious, silky,
smooth, rich.
That's what I was really
looking for.
And the bread does exactly
what it should do
without being too big
of a part of the sandwich,
It's the perfect foil.
Dude, you got it going.
Banh mi is getting pork.
The banh mi is delicious.
Definitely very juicy.
You get that crisp
crunch of the veggies.
They kind of throw
the funk to it?
Yeah, they do a great job
with them.
English muffin,
sausage, egg and cheese.
Love this place, and I come
about five days a week.
You are the center-city
type deli
that everybody wants
to have in their town.
Your pops has got
to be super proud, man.
I like to think so.
Well done.
FIERI: Coming up,
a multigenerational spot
in Ottawa, Canada...
All right, guys,
I dig it.
...keeping the seafood tradition
alive...
I respect the full swing
of the bat here.
...by the pound
and on the plate.
We're taking it
to lobster town.
Is there a lobster town
in Ottawa?
♪♪
I'm here in Ottawa, Canada,
in an area known as Alta Vista,
and about 10 minutes
from the downtown area.
Now you know what we don't see
a lot of anymore?
Freestanding butcher shops.
And you what we don't
even see more of?
Freestanding seafood markets.
But in my hometown, I'm lucky.
I've got Santa Rosa Seafood.
The place is the bomb.
But these folks at Alta Vista,
they got it going on.
They've got their own joint.
It's Pelican Seafood Market
and Grill.
Fire away.
The Pelican Grill is definitely
my go-to spot for seafood.
Cracking.
The food's always fresh.
It's like being at the seashore.
FIERI: And it's become
a family-run Ottawa institution
carried on by brothers-in-law
Jim Foster and Marc Roy.
Marc's dad started
the business way back in 78'.
So Marc and I have been
partners since 1990.
Did it just start
as a fish market?
Yeah, just as a market and then
we added the restaurant in 96'.
FIERI: And they've got
Chef James McMillan
cooking up the catch.
Scallops and belly
up in the window.
This dish is to die for.
Scallops, melt in your mouth.
And then the cherry on top
of the sundae is the pork belly,
which is so rich in flavor.
What are we doing?
Got our pork belly ready
for braising here.
Start with onions,
carrots, celery,
garlic cloves,
thyme -- fresh sprigs.
So I'm going to roast
this open, 400,
for about half an hour,
45 minutes.
We got our apple cider.
Usually get most of it
in the pan?
I usually get most of it
in there.
Not every day. No, I try.
-Cover it.
-You've got it.
-And go for how long?
-Three to four hours.
Got it.
What are we into?
Our parsnip puree.
Butter, onion,
Granny Smith apples.
Wa-bam.
Is that an Emeril I just heard?
Was that a "bam"?
-A "wa-bam."
-It's a Canada Emeril.
We do things a little
differently here.
-Yes, you do.
-Okay.
Stirs it counter-clockwise.
Now the parsnips?
Let that cook down.
And then?
The cream and the water.
Puree it, make it nice
and smooth and silky.
It's going to be
tasty, man.
Let's bring this
all together.
Okay. Scallops, salt and pepper
on there, olive oil.
We're going to move
right in here.
We've got to treat them nice,
like your lady there, bud.
Back.
You put your lady
in hot oil?
[ Laughter ]
So while these
kind of rest out,
we're going to
start searing off
that nice chunk of belly
we got there.
Here's our jus.
Butter, and that's what's going
to thicken it up for us.
Let's see it, Chef.
Apple-parsnip puree.
Beets, some snap peas.
Brussels sprouts
and some green curly kale.
Scallops, pork belly,
waffle fries and the jus.
Voilà.
That's a really good
scallop, man.
You cooked it perfectly.
Super tender,
there's great crust.
The jus is a really
nice complement to it.
That parsnip puree,
now that's dynamite.
The time that you all are
taking here to braise the belly,
and to serve it up
with the seasonal veg,
carries it through.
Nice job, man. Really nice job.
Scallops going in.
Just lovely, tender
and moist, and succulent.
MAN: The pork belly with a
little bit of apple cider
gives it that nice crispiness,
and that subtle dry flavor.
This place has created dishes
that make me come back
over and over and over.
You walk in and you see
the market right away.
This is like a real
deal fish market.
FOSTER: We've got rainbow trout,
haddock and cod, fresh halibut.
MAN: We'll come and pick up
some salmon,
or take it home
and prepare.
Other nights when you just
feel like going out
and being pampered, come here
and have lobster poutine.
You come to Canada, you get
to think about the poutine.
But this isn't
a normal poutine.
WOMAN:
Lots of nice meaty lobster.
The gravy,
it's a lobster bisque blend.
The combination blew me away.
FIERI: Poutine is typically
fries topped with beef gravy,
with curds,
but we're taking it to lobster.
We're taking it
to lobster town.
Is there a lobster town
in Ottawa? Now there is.
-Here. Right here.
-Now there is.
Start with the stock,
but our raw lobster bodies
right on top of our mirepoix.
It's gonna go in the oven.
-How long?
-Two to three hours.
You glaze it with
the white wine right now.
Right into the pot here.
Okay. Water, bay leaf,
and peppercorn.
And how long are we
going to let this go?
-Three hours.
-Next up?
We are going to make
the lobster bisque.
Okay.
Olive oil, white onion,
red pepper, orange carrot.
Because they're out
of the blue ones.
We got our lobster stock, and
we're going to get this pureed.
Say hello
to my little friend.
Thicken this up with our butter
and flour roux.
This is the longest stock
in the world.
-Time for her to go back in.
-All right.
Our brandy
and our Jagermeister,
secret weapon here.
Right into our mixture,
and cream.
This is the bisque
that you're serving
in the restaurant
all the time?
Yeah, so we're going to turn it
into a lobster gravy.
All right, start it up.
Mascarpone and our cream cheese.
We still have cheese curds
to come?
You got it.
Is there a swimsuit season
here in Ottawa?
For about a month.
That's when I'm not going
to eat the cheese curds.
Bring on the lobster.
Let's take out our lobby
straight from the steamer.
-Do you steam them per order?
-Yep.
When you say lobster poutine,
you're not joking.
Fries. So we cut them
by hand every day.
Cheese for the gravy.
And we're going to put the rest
right on top of the fries.
Gravy.
Choooo.
Chives.
What was the noise
that just happened?
You got to make that noise
if you want it
to fall nicely,
you know?
Never in the history
of "Triple D"
have we ever had
a sound-effect seasoning.
♪♪
I respect the full swing
of the bat here.
And I'm thinking I'm going
to get bits of lobster
sprinkled inside
of the poutine,
but when you get it served
in the body of the lobster,
this is higher end.
Wow. I'm getting
all that brandy flavor.
Next level with the cream
cheese, and the mascarpone.
Great fries.
Delicious dish. Well done.
-Right on.
-Lobster poutine.
This ranks probably as one of
the best poutines I've ever had.
And believe me,
I've had a lot of poutines.
The sauce is super silky
and it's perfect.
WOMAN:
This whole dish is so Canadian.
It's red,
like the Canadian flag.
Can you believe they invented
lobsters to turn red
when they're cooked
just for the Canadians?
Coconut shrimp.
I never say no to,
"Let's go to Pelican."
That's for sure.
All right, guys, I dig it.
It's a good-looking place.
And I'll tell you,
freshness prevails.
Nice job.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry,
I'll been looking for more
joints all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives."
Chef you might get the award
for the first person
that's ever worn denim shorts
on "Triple D."
I'm brave if anything.
I'm standing over here.
You are now next to the guy
in the denim shorts.