You know, people are asking
me all the time, hey, Guy,
that one joint you
checked out in that
one city when you were doing
Triple D-- how are they doing?
I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've
seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out, it
was only the beginning.
Because Triple D joints
have been blowing up,
and we're go back to
see what's cooking.
Like on this trip--
we're taking a walk
on the lighter side.
It's really fresh,
healthy, light.
Like the Massachusetts
spot that started it all.
This guy is the
Triple D OG, OG, OG.
Now cutting calories
in familiar favorites.
The times have changed.
People are started
to ask for it.
And in Glendale, California.
Mouth is starting to water.
You feel it, right there.
It starts to water.
A Cuban cafe creating all
kinds of culinary classics.
I just had a moho moment.
Plus, an apres ski spot
in Park City, Utah.
Well, boom, boom, mushroom.
Forking over jackfruit tacos--
I can't say it's good--
after a day of
hitting the slopes--
I can say it's great, though.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is Triple D Nation.
[rock music]
So here it is, ladies and
gentlemen, 13 years later.
This is where Triple D started.
It's pretty amazing, but
all over the country,
places like this, like Kelly's
diner here in Somerville Mass,
are booming again.
50 to 60 years after
serving their very
first meals, the
All-American classics
are as popular as ever--
or even more so.
I can't wait to go back
and check things out--
see how my buddy Jay is doing,
see if he's still rocking it,
or even more so.
I was hoping you were
going to do that.
WOMAN: Kelly's does seem
like a classic diner,
so it does make sense
that Guy would come here.
It was 2006, so I
would have been eleven.
My family and I--
we've been coming here
forever, and it's just awesome.
A lot of history here.
It's a rarity these
days-- this kind of place.
Dying breed.
GUY FIERI: But this
one is still alive
and kicking, thanks to
owner Jay Holmes' devotion
to classic diner food.
They call it comfort food.
It makes you comfortable.
Home made cooking.
Cooking from scratch.
Fresh ingredients.
Everything's got to be fresh.
You haven't aged, by the way.
I appreciate it.
So I've gone to a
lot of restaurants
that we call Triple D OG.
Those are the places that were
in the first couple years.
But this guy is the
Triple D OG OG OG.
This is the one
that started it all.
JAY HOLMES: We were actually the
first diner on the first show
ever.
Guy Fieri was new on the scene.
GUY FIERI: That's all right
here, right now, on Diners,
Drive Ins, and Dives.
You were so gracious.
You didn't know us,
we didn't know you.
I hadn't been doing TV.
You remember the
things that we did.
JAY HOLMES: We did the meatloaf.
And I top it off with
a homemade Alfredo
sauce that has mushrooms in it.
Where did this come from?
I made it up.
So not only are you
the owner of a diner,
now you're turning into a chef.
Oh, yeah.
Big time.
OK.
So give me the rundown.
A little bit of oil.
Heat up the oil.
Mushrooms.
A little bit of
garlic, let that brown.
Add the heavy cream,
put a little basil.
GUY FIERI: And then when do
we add the Parmesan cheese?
JAY HOLMES: After it
starts to reduce a little.
Give it a little whisk.
GUY FIERI: This is, like,
some gourmet meatloaf, dude.
JAY HOLMES: Oh, yeah.
Now I'm just going to put this
over the top of the meatloaf.
I imagine that's not going
to taste just incredible.
It's good.
Look at that.
And you just cook
it right in there?
Cover it up, bake it in the
oven for 45 minutes or so.
So anything
changed on the menu?
JAY HOLMES: We added
an egg white omelet--
Because the
times have changed.
People are starting
to ask for it.
Yeah.
How many eggs are we
going to go through today?
JAY HOLMES: 150 dozen.
GUY FIERI: 150 dozen eggs.
JAY HOLMES: Some people like
to have a little bit more
of a healthier option.
One that we have is called
the spinoccoli omelette.
You saute up tomatoes,
broccoli, spinach.
You add the egg whites
and any type of cheese
that you want to add at the end.
It's pretty simple.
It's delicious.
We offer fresh fruit instead
of home fries for an option.
WAITRESS: Spinoccoli
egg white omelette.
I feel like normally
when you get an omelette,
it's kind of boring, but this
tastes a lot more filling.
I really like the broccoli
and spinach combo.
It's really fresh, it's
healthy, light, not greasy.
You're doing great breakfast
items, great lunch items.
MAN: You'd be surprised how many
people come in here, especially
on Fridays.
Their seafood is excellent.
The lobster roll-- yeah.
It's excellent.
My fish guy, Joe, he'll
call me up and give me--
- My fish guy, Joe.
- Yeah.
Fish guy Joe.
GUY FIERI: Not everybody
has a fish guy Joe.
JAY HOLMES: He'll call me
up and he'll give me a deal.
He'll say, I've got a
great deal on culls,
which are one claw lobsters.
GUY FIERI: One claw lobsters.
Yeah.
And that's because
they're grown with one claw,
or because--
I think it's--
legend has it, they got into
a fight and lost a claw.
The legend of the
one clawed lobster.
Mix it up with mayonnaise,
celery salt, celery.
Now, where did this
recipe come from?
Right up here.
It's all up here.
Chop up all the meat.
Big chunks.
There we go.
A little celery salt.
Right there, behind you.
Little shake.
Yeah.
- Is that enough?
- That's enough.
OK.
How much mayonnaise do we use?
JAY HOLMES: As little as
you can, just to cover
the lobster a little bit.
You don't want to put
too much mayonnaise.
GUY FIERI: And that's it?
JAY HOLMES: That's it.
GUY FIERI: That's all we mix in?
It bet you that's good.
I should try it,
don't you think?
Yeah.
Try some.
I'm dying to try it.
I like how you put just
a little bit of mayonnaise
in there.
It doesn't mask all the flavor.
All the lobster
really comes out.
Yeah.
That's good stuff, man.
JAY HOLMES: It's a huge seller.
The customer right
there just got it.
Smart customer.
GUY FIERI: Coming up--
between the plates--
the corned beef
hash this dude makes is legit--
and the personality--
I got nothing else to
do but let him do my work.
GUY FIERI: The walk down
memory lane continues.
Look at this.
That's mind blowing.
So I'm back where it all
started, Kelly's diner.
The actual OG Triple D diner
I visited back in 2006.
It really put the diner on
the map from that point on,
and it was fun to do.
I can tell when
I walk in here,
you have not changed one thing.
JAY HOLMES: This is
a 1953 classic diner,
so I like to keep
it all original.
I did the booths a little
bit of a different color.
GUY FIERI: OK.
JAY HOLMES: That's it.
GUY FIERI: Wow.
You're really living
on the edge, right now.
And is this a computer?
Yeah.
I think the last
time I remember
Joni doing bad chicken scratch
and doing the math herself.
JONI: I feel like
your secretary.
GUY FIERI: You have to
have, like, track shoes on.
Joni was here.
JONI: I have to get Sweet'N Low.
You just bring
it over in hand.
JONI: Yeah.
We don't put them in a--
JONI: Nothing fancy here.
JAY HOLMES: No.
She's passed.
Marion was here.
GUY FIERI: Just running
the counter, talking smack.
JAY HOLMES: Yeah.
Unfortunately, she's passed.
MARION: Give her
some more coffee,
you've got it in your hand.
I've got nothing else to
do but let him do my work.
I appreciate you letting
me train under your tutelage.
Oh, honey, if I trained you.
They're just classic
diner waitresses.
You can say most
anything to the customers
because they come in
here expecting that.
Oh, you've got
decisions already.
JAY HOLMES: They were great.
GUY FIERI: That's so sad.
This was honestly my first
real experience about being
in a diner-- a big diner.
I got to see how
people were working,
I got to see how busy
you were in the back.
I really don't think
to show would have got
picked up had we not had the
opportunity to come here.
And I think that
would put me on first--
helping you guys out a lot.
So--
I'm glad he knows that.
Looks like everybody's
still doing the same thing.
You're still doing
the corned beef hash?
JAY HOLMES: Oh, yeah.
The corned beef hash
this dude makes is legit.
It's the bomb.
I just had some.
Same recipe to this day.
It's my grandfather's
recipe, actually.
He had a great recipe
for corned beef hash,
showed us how to do it this
way, and we never turned back.
Everybody loved it.
We use a red corned beef and
we boil it for three or four
hours until it's very tender.
You cut it up into pieces
so it's easy to grind,
then you add in the onions,
potatoes, and grind that down.
What are you going to
do, buy it in the can?
That's the worst.
Mix it up, and you
put it in the oven
to bake for about 45 minutes.
After the corned beef is
baked, it goes on the flat top.
You put a weight on it and
it comes off nice and crispy.
That's how 90% of
the people like it.
We serve it with two
eggs anyway you like it
and your choice of toast.
It's called the number
eight on the menu
and it's a huge seller.
Actually, it's a
good hangover meal.
WAITRESS: Corned beef hash.
It's crispy on the top and
kind of smooth and creamy
on the bottom.
It's really rich.
Nice and salty,
very flavorful.
It's your classic
corned beef hash,
but it's taken to
the next level.
Oh.
Nothing got more real
when I just look at this.
We shot here in August of '06.
This is may of 2019.
That's mind blowing.
You've got to know something.
You're a legend.
I wouldn't go that far.
No, trust me.
You are.
You're the real deal, buddy.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
Thanks, man.
That's awesome.
This makes my whole week.
JAY HOLMES: You
guys are the best.
GUY FIERI: And coming up in
California-- take a whiff--
the nose knows just where
to find the real deal.
Wait a second.
That's Cuban food.
And man, it's worth the hunt.
This is a culinary
shot glass of fun.
Los Angeles is a cornucopia
of cultural cuisine,
so it's no surprise that
back in 2009 I literally--
and I mean literally--
sniffed out
this family run Cuban joint.
A few months ago, I was
sitting in that intersection
right there when these
flavors from this restaurant
started to flow into the car,
and I said, wait a second.
That's Cuban food.
And they're still
whipping up fresh recipes
done the old fashioned way.
This is Mambos.
[cuban music]
[speaking spanish]
I discovered this place before
Triple D discovered this place.
A classic Cuban restaurant.
The food is not pretentious,
but it's delicious.
GUY FIERI: What else would
you expect from owner Raul
Gonzalez, who opened this place
in '88 with his wife, Mima,
and son, Raul Jr.
I pulled up and I
thought mom was boss.
She is, though.
My wife, Mima-- she is one
to show me how to cook.
She educates you,
you write the recipes,
and you two are doing it.
RAUL GONZALEZ JR.:
We had a lot of fun.
We got a taste of the real
Guy, and he's the real deal.
Think I can have a
job here on the weekend?
I'll park the car out front.
People come by and check it out.
What's going on?
Who's the spiky, blond
haired Cuban guy in the back?
Yeah.
We can make some reasoning.
He gave me the
opportunity to introduce
my food in the United States.
I appreciate that very much.
OK.
What are we making?
We're going to make
the tostones rellenos.
You're doing it with shrimp?
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: Yeah.
We cut the shrimp, garlic--
I like the way you're
going with this right now.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.:
Sitting in lemon.
In lemon.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: Onions,
tomatoes, cilantro.
You've got to mix
those together.
More lemon.
GUY FIERI: So how long
does that marinate?
Two hours.
GUY FIERI: Then we
make the tostones?
You're right.
GUY FIERI: This is the plantain.
We're going to fry it.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.:
Take a few minutes.
And I'm going to
smash it, right?
You're right.
He says he's got
something special.
Oh.
GUY FIERI: What
are we going to do?
Are we going to put
a hole in this thing?
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: Yeah.
Sit in here and press.
GUY FIERI: You
make tostone cups?
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: Yeah.
I want a tostone cup maker.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: I need that.
You do.
So do I.
We wound up giving him as
a gift the tostone maker.
I just was holding onto it.
I didn't want it to
fall off of the counter.
Are they ready?
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.: Yeah.
GUY FIERI: Let's pull them.
Look at that.
And now we're
going to fill them.
My mouth is starting--
you know, right there,
it starts to water.
This is a culinary
shot glass of fun.
It's awesome.
Really nice texture
of the shrimp.
Look at it.
It's still holding the juice.
I make three times more
than what we usually make.
RAUL GONZALEZ JR.: Now my dad
introduced a stuffed avocado
with mahi mahi.
I just took it to
a whole new level.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR.:
We are now making
the mahi mahi and Maria sauce.
Cut the mahi mahi in small
pieces and put it on the grill.
Take the fish, put
it over the avocado.
Then the Maria sauce.
Flour, garlic, bell
peppers, onions,
jalapenos, chicken
powder, cilantro, saffron,
black pepper, some water.
RAUL GONZALEZ JR.: Avocado
mahi mahi, order up.
Melt in your mouth delicious.
The mahi mahi is
just like butter,
and the combination of the
avocado and the salsa on top--
very good.
MAN: The way they prepare it--
absolutely delicious.
And I know it's giving me
good health, eating this food.
The food's very wholesome.
Very natural.
What you see is what you get.
Garlic and lemon juice and
salt and pepper, and we're
going to blend it up and
we're going to make mojo.
RAUL GONZALEZ SR:
First, garlic, salt,
a little pepper, lemon, wine.
And we blend.
GUY FIERI: And that's it.
Yep.
In 2009, Guy was
in the red light.
I was sitting out there
at the traffic light.
And he had the sunroof open.
That's what I smelled.
And he smelled the mojo.
The garlic.
Take a whiff.
He came in.
It was totally spontaneous--
you know, unexpected.
You like the mojo?
I love the mojo.
You've got to love that.
I just had a mojo moment.
RAUL GONZALEZ JR.:
Now the mojo is
on the tostones steak sandwich.
We make the steak
with some mojo.
We cut in half and
fry the plantains.
RAUL GONZALEZ JR.: Instead of
using a baguette for a steak
sandwich, let's pound
it, let's re-fry it,
let's throw some steak
on it-- some red onions,
some pico de gallo, cilantro,
avocado, and it's good
and it's light.
Table two, tostones
steak sandwich.
It has the crunch
of the tostones,
the soft of the
avocado, and then
the juiciness of the steak.
MAN: It's the type of plantain
that's not super sweet.
It was all amazing.
Simple ingredients
with a lot of flavor.
I think you guys are kind of
leading the way in California
about taking Cuban
food out there.
Thank goodness mom's boss.
Yeah.
Now, mom may be the boss,
but those fresh Cuban feasts
really rule this Cali spot.
And coming up, at a ski resort,
a place in Park City, Utah--
This is basically
an umami bomb.
GUY FIERI: With comfort
plates to warm you up.
You've got a sweet and
heat a meat can't beat.
And vegan spins that
won't weigh you down.
Back in 2014, I found
a surprising spot
at the base of a ski
lift in Park City, Utah.
It was dishing out anything
but your average slope
side standards.
And nowadays, you can still find
good grub plus fresh new spins
at the Silver Star cafe.
WAITRESS: Pork osso bucco.
You think about these
dishes when you're not here
and you want to come
back and get them again.
After a day of skiing, you're
looking for something more
than a dog and a hamburger.
Here it is, Silver Star--
where you get fantastic food,
great people, great area.
GUY FIERI: That's exactly
what I thought when
I hit the place up in 2014.
Look at that.
I've been in the restaurant
business all my life.
The stress of working
in the restaurant
is completely turned
off when you have this.
And that's pretty much
what Jeff and Lisa
Ward were looking for when
they opened this place in 2010.
I just want to know
whose idea this was.
I think it was
a combined idea.
You and your daughter?
Yeah.
How's the average
skier taking this?
The average
skier that comes in
loves it, because we're right
here at the bottom of the chair
cooking it from scratch.
We're cooking it to order.
WAITER: Mushroom stroganoff.
OK.
So we're going to be making
the spaetzle for the vegetarian
mushroom stroganoff.
Love me some spaetzle.
We'll start off
with the flour.
Sift it.
[makes swishing noise]
Oh sorry, sound effects.
- No.
I like it.
When Guy visited last time, we
had a chef who was helping us.
It was fun watching Guy work
with Dave when he was here.
Good, chef.
We're done.
OK.
Create a little hole, there.
Toss in the eggs.
A little warmed milk,
a little water, salt.
Start working it with my hands.
You want a really
nice, sticky dough.
I've got a spaetzle
maker over here.
(SINGING) Roll
out the spaetzle.
Yes, sir.
We're just going to take it
into this little scoopy thingy.
So you just slide it into the
boiling water, back and forth.
The sliding action will actually
cut the dough once it goes in.
And we just put
it in an ice bath
and then we saute it
at the time of service.
So now we're going
to assemble the dish.
Get a little oil on the pan.
Red onion, a touch
of garlic, mushrooms.
Give it a little toss.
One of the keys to this is
the roasted vegetable stock.
Add a little bit of sour
cream right off the bat.
That's where you kind of get
that classic stroganoff flavor.
Chive, salt, pepper.
We're going to be
plating the spaetzle.
This is the mushroom.
Just a touch more sour cream,
and then a little bit of chive.
There you go.
That is the vegetarian
mushroom stroganoff.
Boom, boom, mushroom.
I wanted this to be good.
I just can't say it's good.
I can say it's great, though.
He just kept digging in.
We appreciate seeing that.
My friend, you've
done quite well.
Thank you very much.
The food they
made on Triple D--
Outrageous.
MAN: --everyone loves it--
Wow.
MAN: --but they keep freshening
up the menu with new options,
as well.
So about a year and a half
ago, I took over as head chef
in the kitchen.
Yeah, those are looking good.
We wanted to focus on
a little lighter style.
We opted to come up
with a vegan recipe.
These are our vegan
jackfruit tacos.
So we heat a pan with
a little bit of oil.
We add diced onion.
We'll let that go until
it starts to soften.
Now I'm going to
add our jackfruit,
and we'll let this cook a
bit and get a little color.
We'll add just a touch of oil,
fresh garlic, chili powder,
paprika, salt and pepper.
We use quite a bit of
seasoning here to give
nice flavor to the jackfruit.
Warm our tortillas.
These are ready, nice and warm.
A mixture of green
and red cabbage.
Jackfruit filling.
Now we're going to add
the red pepper crema.
It's got roasted
red bell peppers,
cashews, almonds,
nutritional yeast,
which adds a little bit of a
cheesy flavor to the crema.
Garlic powder, almond
milk, salt and pepper.
Run it for three or so
minutes until it thickens.
Now we'll add a dollop of our
cherry tomato pico de gallo.
Jackfruit tacos are ready.
WOMAN: Jackfruit has
the texture of meat.
It has a little bit of spice,
just the right amount of heat.
It's not heavy,
fill-your-belly food.
They're delicious.
These are incredible
things and it really
shows the creativity that Jeff
has brought to this restaurant
now that he's behind the line.
The guests seem to be
responding well to the food.
I love the Brussels sprouts.
JEFF WARD: We take
fresh Brussels sprouts,
fry them until they start
to crisp up, drain them,
and put them in the pizza oven.
I want to crisp
them up a little bit
and have some of that bitterness
that comes from the char.
We serve that with a
fish sauce caramel,
which is water and sugar--
we let that cook
and start to color.
Take it off the heat, add
some brown sugar, fish
sauce, salt and lime juice.
Stir to mix all that.
Mix things up just a bit.
This is basically
an umami bomb--
really rich in flavor.
Garnish with some crispy garlic
chips, freshly sliced Fresno
chili, and a slice of lime.
WAITRESS: Fried Brussels
sprouts for you.
MAN: They're really kind
of this great balance
of sweet, spicy, with that
garlic and that Asian fusion.
It's one of those
addicting plates.
It's sweet, it's salty, it's
a little bit hot in the end.
The fried garlic on
top gives it a crunch.
You just want to keep
having another bite.
You've got a sweet and
heat a meat can't beat.
At a ski resort.
Being featured on the show--
it's the gift that
keeps on giving.
People plan their
vacations around the fact
that they've seen
us on the show.
GUY FIERI: Have you
ever seen a place
at the bottom of a ski run
that has food like this?
No.
Yourself?
I rest my case, your honor.
I mean, the evidence.
The evidence is overwhelming.
These Triple D joints
are making the case
for fresh and healthy takes
alongside oldies but goodies.
From the original
Triple D OG, Kelly's
Diner in Somerville Mass,
where the decor may stay retro,
but the menu keeps
up with the times.
And Mambos cafe, where
the aroma of classic Cuban
calls to you in
Glendale, California.
And the Silver Star
cafe in Park City,
Utah, with new, lighter dishes
to help you shred the slopes.
And we'll keep checking
in with all the old school
Triple D joints right
here on Triple D nation.
What is that?
This is great people watching.
Does this go on all the time?
CHEF: That does
happen quite a bit.
GUY FIERI: Crazy.