You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing
'Triple D,' how did they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning,
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking,
like on this trip.
Is this awesome
or what?
We're uncovering all kinds
of cultural cooking
all over the country.
What?
You said the camera
was off.
In Honolulu...
I am tripping out.
...a French chef
serving fresh fish...
Crazy good, mm.
But it's not just the food
that blew me away.
This is one of
the greatest successes
I've seen out of
"Triple D."
Wow.
-Yeah.
-Plus...
-Hey.
...it's a Salvadoran spot
in Santa Fe
Mmm!
...stirring up
scratch-made sauces...
That's money, dude.
...and pupusas
by the pound...
Ah, I can't wait
to try this.
...and a Middle Eastern mecca
in Texas...
Do you airmail?
Load a trunk up.
...proving they still deserve
to wear the crown.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Prince of North Arlington.
Familiar faces...
Nice to meet you.
...new places and more
off-the-hook flavors,
this is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So here we are in Honolulu
at Pier 38.
Now, back in 2010,
we came to shoot
this funky little lunch counter,
a little sandwich shop.
I don't even know
what to call it,
but it was a big favorite
of all the fishermen
and all the dock workers.
Well, some time has passed,
and I hear that things
have changed a bit.
This is Nico's Pier 38.
Fish loco moco.
Been coming to Nico's
for a while now,
one of my favorite
places to get fish.
We love coming here because
they make you feel like family.
Enjoy.
Shortly after the "Triple D"
episode aired,
a lot of people started coming
down from all over the world.
FIERI: Which is fitting,
because owner Nico Chaize
is an international man
of mystery.
You come from France
and open
a French-Hawaiian-California
seafood restaurant.
That's it.
And back in 2010,
that restaurant was about
900 square feet.
Now? Uh, not so much.
Hang on a second.
I am tripping out.
Dude, you had
a tiny lunch spot.
CHAIZE: 10 times bigger than
what it used to be, 245 seats.
How many was in
the last one? 12?
-How about 20, yeah.
-I love it.
I tell everybody when I leave,
"The residents of Flavortown
are going to come visit you.
Get ready."
Bro,
nobody has done this.
Even though it's way bigger
than the old one,
Nico is still cooking
and creating.
The food is just as awesome
as it always was.
So what are we going to make,
Chef?
CHAIZE: Opah with stuffed crab
and a watercress-cream sauce.
-Great.
-We got the opah ready to go.
I'm taking the skin off.
From there, we're going to cut
about a 7-ounce portion.
Pretty firm fish.
Pretty moist,
it cuts really well.
Okay,
so now what happens?
So now we're going to fill that
with a crab stuffing, onions,
celery, garlic,
saute with olive oil
and deglaze it
in a white wine, fresh thyme,
and then we add in
crab meat.
Smash it up.
Dijon mustard, cayenne pepper,
heavy cream, some panko
added in to thick it out.
♪♪
Opah time.
Olive oil, you have the fish
crab side down first.
Quick both sides. Look at that.
Finish in the oven.
Yeah, 10 minutes,
it'll be ready.
Now what happens?
We're going to make
a watercress-cream sauce --
some olive oil, onions, garlic,
dry thyme, whole lemon...
-The whole lemon.
-...white wine.
You have the TV hand,
the pour.
-Add on chicken stock.
-That's reduced down.
Now we add the cream?
When it's done, strain it.
Nice, you see that?
You see the teamwork?
-In the blender.
Nice fresh watercress,
jalapenos.
-Jalapeño.
-Jalapenos?
"Peño," it's "peño."
The green thing.
[ Laughter ]
Put the lid on it.
Okay,
it's ready to go.
Blend it, and that's it.
-That looks great.
His opah out of the oven,
the watercress-cream sauce
right over the fish.
Look at that. Mmm!
Crazy good.
The watercress
with the jalapeños in it
is out of bounds.
What?
You said the camera
was off.
Did the menu change,
or is it still the food
that people can afford when
they come down here to work?
Yeah, same thing we had
on the old place,
takeout containers
at lunchtime.
-Really?
-So yeah.
MAN: Down here is a great place
for lunch.
You know that the fish
that you're getting is probably
the freshest fish
on the island.
FIERI: That's because Nico
is still getting his fish
from the fish auction
at the pier.
Is this awesome
or what?
As a chef, I mean,
this is the kind of stuff
that I want to come
and see.
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
and fish markets.
The official
in the fish market
didn't want to let Guy in
because he was wearing slippers,
and you have to wear
covered shoes.
Big dude.
We had to
talk to him about it.
Thank you, brother.
I'm going to get some boots now.
It was good fun.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Bell ringing ]
9.10, 9.20, 30.
Hey, what's up with that?
9.30 going.
I have no clue
what's going on right now.
-That's expensive.
-Yeah.
CHAIZE:
Guy put a price tag on it.
It was way too high.
It was twice as much more
expensive as the normal price.
You got taken on that one,
what a dummy bid.
[ Laughter ]
This is a fresh ahi bigeye tuna
from the fish auction
for our furikake ahi
with cilantro dip.
WOMAN: Furikake ahi
with the cilantro dip.
First, we have to coat
the fish in a furikake spice,
which is pretty much
dry seaweed,
sesame seed, salt and pepper.
Quick sear on both sides,
5 to 10 seconds to be done,
and now we've got to
make our cilantro dip.
First, we can add our garlic,
our ginger,
our Worcestershire sauce,
cilantro,
lemon juice, mayonnaise.
Cilantro dip,
got one furikake pickup.
Crusty on the outside and nice
and tender on the inside,
it is very good.
-The fish is so fresh.
I really like it paired with
the garlic cilantro dip
that's just so creamy.
Outdoor patio,
a huge bar.
-There is more.
-There's more?
Yeah.
FIERI: Coming up...
This is the exact reason
we do the show.
...Nico's island empire
still has me in shock...
I feel like I just watched
Hunter or Ryder hit a home run.
...with his gangbuster growth
and his hits
from his own country.
You and the French
in the pate.
C'est bon.
One loco moco
over easy eggs.
FIERI:
In 2010, I stopped by Nico's
Pier 38 in Honolulu Harbor.
This is where all
the fishing boats come in
and drop off their catch
that go to the auction,
and back then Nico
was serving fresh fish to go
in a tiny little spot.
What's the future?
Fine-dining restaurant?
No, I'm from fine dining.
I don't want to go back to it.
Famous last words.
-There's more?
-Yeah, the restaurant upstairs.
-What is that one?
-It's the fine dining of Nico's.
That's where I do my
French cooking, upstairs.
Mahi-mahi.
This is the exact reason
we do the show.
Every time I look at the poster,
I always remember that.
I'm in the hallway
to the restroom?
-Yeah.
-That's where you put me?
You remember what you wrote
on the poster?
I forgot all about it.
It says, "Nico's,
the fast-food chain killer."
[ Laughter ]
And there's a reason
for that.
Fresh marlin burger,
okay.
So there's a fresh marlin cubed.
That's about it.
You and the French
in the pate.
Yeah, it's fine diced onions,
fresh green garlic,
Dijon mustard.
-C'est bon.
C'est bon.
Dry dill weed.
Marlin-dill sandwich.
Tabasco, some olive oil,
homemade tartar sauce.
A binder.
-Lemon zest.
-Okay.
Take the juice out
of those two lemons.
Lime zest,
lime juice, mix it.
Portion it on patties,
and there we're going
to put the marlin burger.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
That is a big burger.
Dude, that smokes
any fast food.
Look at all the juice
coming out of that.
They should call you
the fast-food killer.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
And he's still killing it
with his own twist
on classic Hawaiian staples
like the loco moco.
The real loco moco
is hamburger patties.
We're known for fish, so we
came up with a fish loco moco.
We're going to put salt
and white pepper on the fish,
butter on the flattop.
Good, simmer to 10 minutes
to cook it all the way through.
The loco moco is usually
with brown gravy.
Using bechamel,
the classic sauce from France.
Put the milk first, nutmeg,
salt and white pepper,
Swiss cheese and Gruyere cheese,
and we're going to thick it out
with a roux,
which is butter and flour.
We want the fish taste
into the bechamel,
so we are making a fish stock,
and we're going to add it
into the bechamel.
We are going to put the rice,
gravy,
and then we're going to put
the fish and a fried egg on top.
Fish loco moco picking up.
-Loco moco.
It's nice and light
with the fish
and the bechamel sauce,
very flavorful.
MAN: It has, like, a creamy,
buttery sauce.
Here in Hawaii, we say,
"Ono," which means delicious.
The mahi-mahi is very ono.
♪♪
You know
what I feel like?
I feel like I just watched
Hunter or Ryder hit a home run.
You know?
This is one of
the greatest successes
I've seen out of "Triple D."
-Thank you.
What are the next steps?
I'm taking
a little break.
Maybe, you think?
♪♪
Nico definitely deserves
a little R & R after all that.
Just don't stay away
too long, buddy.
The people of Flavortown
really need you.
Now coming up in Santa Fe...
Pupusa for table six.
I don't think that
I've ever had pupusa.
...a chef from El Salvador...
-You can try it today.
-Look at that.
...shows me what
I've been missing.
Mm! You have completely
trainwrecked me, man.
You better get
a bigger restaurant.
FIERI:
In all my travels, I'm used
to popping into Mexican joints
throughout the Southwest.
Back in 2009, I found a spot
in Santa Fe
serving up real-deal
Salvadoran cuisine,
and the owner is still
whipping up cultural classics
from his own country.
This is Tune-Up Café.
♪♪
I heard about it
because of "Triple D,"
so I wanted to check it out.
The food was so wonderful.
Chile relleno up.
It's authentic, and everything
is delicious every time.
MAN #2: When you eat the food,
you know it's good.
You just keep coming back.
FIERI: And people are still
flocking to it because of...
Hey.
...Jesus Rivera's scratch-made
Salvadoran staples.
So what are we going
to make now?
Getting ready
for the pupusas.
I don't think that
I've ever had pupusa.
No?
You can try it today.
This is going to be the beef
that's going to go
in the pupusa.
-Yeah.
A little bit of oil down,
onions, this is the flank steak.
Wow, making a lot.
Yeah, I love flank steak, too.
So that will all brown up.
Now it's time
for the tomatoes
and the peppers.
-Chile pasado.
Yeah.
Salt and pepper.
So then cook all that up.
How long is it going to take?
-One hour is enough.
Okay, so show me what...
-Tortilla masa.
-Okay.
This is for you.
That's how he did it.
Next, like that.
You don't skimp
on the portions.
You give a lot.
Yeah, enough.
Next is corn,
Monterey Jack cheese.
-Monterey Jack cheese...
-Yeah.
...with the
El Salvadorian dish?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, okay.
Now what happens?
-Fold the pupusa.
Put it in the middle like that.
-Alright.
Look at that.
RIVERA:
We cook the pupusas.
-So now we flip them over.
-Like this.
-Oh.
Perfect.
Look. This is the cheese
melting inside.
-Ah, I can see it.
-This is ready.
Let's go put in
tomato sauce on top.
-Look at that.
-Try it.
Mmm! Crazy good.
That does it.
You have completely
trainwrecked me, man.
The first time he tried pupusas,
I'm so proud about it.
After the show, people from
everywhere come and eat pupusa.
Lamb barbacoa tacos are one
of my favorite dishes here.
This is lamb shoulder.
I do salt first, pepper
and then a layer
of vegetables at the bottom.
Now I'm ready to put the
shoulders, then more vegetables.
Mexican oregano, fresh thyme,
salt, black pepper, dark beer.
Now we pour in the chile ancho
and chipotle.
First, dry chile anchos,
chile chipotle, water,
boil for about 10 minutes.
♪♪
And then that's going to cook
5 to 6 hours at 350.
Now I'm ready to make
my lamb barbacoa tacos.
Spinach, salt and pepper,
fresh garlic,
lamb, refried beans,
Spanish rice, cilantro onions,
Cotija cheese.
FIERI:
And spicy roasted-tomato salsa.
Smells great.
-Thanks.
No, I said,
"It smells great," not you.
Oh, okay, it's the tomatoes,
not me.
What else we going
to put in there?
Water, the chile anchos
and chile guajillo
and chile de arbol.
This is when it really
gets silly right here.
Look at that thing.
Look at that.
The roasted-tomato salsa,
mmm, killer.
Lamb barbacoa taco
for table nine.
There's just the right amount
of salty and very smoky.
I just really love that lamb.
When I'm in the spicy mood,
I get the lamb barbacoa tacos,
and the sauce
that comes with it
is even spicier
than what it's marinated in.
FIERI:
But if spicy isn't your thing...
This is our mole sauce for the
mole Colorado chicken enchilada.
This is the best dish I have.
Sauteed onions and garlic,
toasted sesame seeds,
toasted walnuts,
crispy corn tortillas,
chocolate, I like the flavor.
Raisins, dry chile anchos,
tomato paste,
cloves, whole black peppercorn,
salt, cinnamon, fresh oregano
and fresh thyme,
grilled bananas,
grilled tomatoes,
chicken stock,
boil it for about 45 minutes.
Now I'm ready to blend it.
♪♪
Now we're making
chicken enchiladas.
♪♪
Put mole on top, Oaxaca cheese.
Put it in the boiler
to melt the cheese.
Mole Colorado
for table seven is ready.
I love the counterbalance of
the sweet on top of the spicy.
It just creates this
beautiful clash of flavors.
It's a little bit sweet,
a little bit savory,
just complex
and really interesting.
That's money, dude.
I think you might want to think
about expanding.
You better get a bigger
restaurant.
He told me I need to expand,
and I did it.
The bar is new.
I have more employees.
We got so busy.
So you come to
the United States,
and you open
your own restaurant,
and now Food Network
is at your restaurant.
What next?
That's the whole
dream there.
-Awesome.
-It was a dream.
Having "Triple D" in my
restaurant is the best dream.
♪♪
Definitely not a dream,
Jesus, your Salvadoran flavors
are still selling out
in Santa Fe.
Now coming up in Dallas...
You've got to
check this out. Mm!
...Middle Eastern meals...
Handmade by the guy
in the dress shirt.
...that'll make
your mouth water.
That's your Lebanese drive-in
that you find in Texas
between a bunch of Mexican
restaurants close to a hospital.
It's not every day I get
to hang out with royalty,
but back in 2009
I found myself
in the presence of a prince,
the Prince of
North Arlington, Texas,
and these days his palace
is a little more spacious,
and he's passed down the crown.
This is Prince Lebanese Grill.
WOMAN:
It made me so happy to see
Prince Lebanese Grill
on "Triple D."
It's a favorite place
of many people in Arlington.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Their whole devotion
to good food,
that's what I love about it.
FIERI: That's because owner
Francis Kobty
is devoted
to sharing his family's
Middle Eastern recipes
with the masses,
and that's made him a bit
of a celebrity around here.
So you're the
Prince of North Arlington?
The Prince
of North Arlington.
When I say that,
you've got to have, like, a move
or something, you know.
Is that...
-Do that kind of move or...
Okay, you've got to
give me something.
When I say, "Prince,"
you have to give me, like, a...
Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
-Alright.
-Yeah.
From that show until now,
most people call me Prince.
-Yeah.
-Alright.
[ Laughter ]
And what's the name
of this dish?
This is called
mashwi shish.
Oh.
How do you spell that?
Beef tenderloin,
Montreal steak seasoning.
-Montreal steak seasoning?
-Yes, sir.
A little mustard seed,
coriander.
And allspice.
Okay, so we've got that
all seasoned up.
This is olive oil.
-From Lebanon?
-That's the one I really like.
Now, will you let this
marinade?
For almost about 24 hours.
Apple cider vinegar.
Just mix it up
a little bit here.
Okay.
We're going to start
the rice pilaf.
We got some vermicellis,
and we fry it. This is corn oil.
That's how I start off
all my dishes,
frying
my uncooked pasta.
FRANCIS: Just wait until it
becomes a little bit more brown.
Put the rice in there,
and the rice has already
been soaked and washed.
Mm-hmm, so dried herbs,
chicken stock, fried vermicelli
and some basmati rice?
You, too, can start
your rice pilaf
at your Lebanese drive-in
that you find in Texas
between a bunch of Mexican
restaurants close to a hospital.
Nice hot grill.
Cut it into a butterfly.
[ Chuckles ]
Look at that.
Because I'm a starch junkie,
you know
I've got to go
after this pilaf first.
[ Chuckles ]
Great texture, very creamy,
handmade by the guy
in the dress shirt.
You've got to
check this out.
FIERI:
These days, that dress shirt
has seen a little less action
since the Prince's son Aziz
has taken over the kitchen.
Aziz is doing a fantastic job.
He cooks everything.
He came up with
his own new dishes.
FIERI: Like
the Prince Lebanese special.
It is our
flame-grilled sampler.
We'll start first
with our Kefta kebabs.
We got some fresh parsley,
rough chopped onions,
jalapeño and garlic.
Add in our seasonings.
We're going to dump it straight
on top with the ground beef,
and we're going to do
fresh parsley, diced onions.
Hand mix it, and we're going
to shape our kebabs
and get them ready
for the grill.
Next thing we're going to do
is our chicken kebab.
We call it shish taouk.
We're going to go ahead
and start with yogurt,
a little onion, a couple whole
lemons, garlic and jalapeños.
It's going to have curry,
oregano, lemon pepper
and a whole bunch
of other seasonings.
We're going to pour this
directly on top
of our chicken breasts
and marinade it
and let it sit
for about 24 hours.
To finish out
the Prince Lebanese special,
we're going to have our steak
medallions and our mechoui lamb.
This is the same marinade
we did with Guy.
We're going to start grilling.
We're going to add our meats --
shish-taouk chicken,
boneless leg of lamb,
and the tower-fillet beef
medallion, ground-beef kebabs.
We're going to plate it
with our vermicelli rice.
Finish with a little bit
of fresh chopped parsley.
Prince Lebanese special.
MAN: I like the spice.
I really like lamb,
and the beef as well,
it's like a velvet texture.
It's all so juicy.
It's not dry.
The chicken has got the good
heavy grill marks.
Anything with grill marks
is good in my book.
Mm! Do you airmail?
Load a trunk up?
I'll drive it up there
for you.
When Guy came in,
this was it, 32 seats only,
and from that time
it just went unbelievable.
Now we seat about 150.
FIERI: And more seats
means more folks eating up
those cultural classics.
WOMAN:
Chicken shawarma is great.
It's my favorite thing
on the menu.
It's what I've always ordered.
It's what I always recommend.
This is one of our most
popular entrees.
Diced chicken, just a little bit
of olive oil
and corn oil mix,
apple cider vinegar,
the family's recipe
on the shawarma seasoning.
It's seasoned salt,
cinnamon, nutmeg,
cumin powder, white pepper,
red pepper, black pepper.
We're going to roll it
around a little bit.
This marinade is going to sit
for 24 hours.
We're going to add our onions,
lemon juice and garlic on,
fresh diced tomato,
shawarma seasoning,
touch of the oil,
house-made hot sauce.
Shawarma plate up.
The chicken is always juicy,
cooked perfectly.
WOMAN #2:
You really get a lot of spice
and a little kick
of almost sweet at the end,
and the rice is cooked
perfectly.
-Prince, I've had a blast.
-Thank you, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Prince of North Arlington.
Thanks.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
[ Laughs ]
The Prince and his heir
are definitely still cooking up
feasts fit for a king,
and so is Nico in Honolulu,
whose little lunch spot
is now a culinary castle,
and in Santa Fe
where Jesus reigns supreme
with his Salvadoran delights.
But they're not the only
diner dynasties we've seen,
so we'll check in on more
next time on "Triple D Nation."
-[ Chuckles ]
-That's cool.
Did you pound this shank out
when you were in the joint?
-Yes.
-I've got to get a spoon shank.
We'll hammer one out
for you.
"We'll hammer one out
We'll be in the back."