You know people are asking
me all the time, hey, Guy,
that one joint you checked
out in that one city,
when you were doing Triple
D, how're they doing?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[car engine reving]
GUY FIERI: Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous dude.
But it turns out it
was only the beginning,
because Triple D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
[car engine reving]
Like on this trip.
It's a melting pot of
savory, spicy, and soupy.
I'm shaking.
I can't get it on the spoon.
GUY FIERI: A pizza
place in Santa Fe.
That rocks.
GUY FIERI: With New
Mexican ingredients.
I got to have more pizza
with green chilies on it.
GUY FIERI: In just
about everything.
That's what I'm talking about.
Spicy shrimp up.
GUY FIERI: My
Hawaiian doppelganger.
Hair looks good.
GUY FIERI: Cooking
up outrageous oxtail.
O- M- G.
GUY FIERI: In a surprising spot.
[bowling pins rattle]
And in Baltimore, a place
serving the state seafood.
Look at the size of that lump.
In soups, sandwiches,
and shells.
Take me dancing.
[laughs]
GUY FIERI: Familiar
faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is Triple D nation.
So back in 2014, we
were here in Honolulu,
not too far from the airport.
And we went to a funky
joint in a bowling alley.
You remember the place?
Mm-mm.
GUY FIERI: Oh, yeah, the
chef had hair just like mine.
And the ox tails.
O- M- G.
GUY FIERI: It's time
for a little revisit.
This is the Alley
Restaurant at Aiea Bowl.
[bowling pins clacking]
Tasty chicken plate up.
Feels like we're eating fine
dining out of a bowling alley.
After Triple D aired,
and you wait to get in,
but it's worth it.
Hats off to Glenn for taking
over the Alley Restaurant
and really making it his own.
GUY FIERI: He's
talking about Chef
Glenn Uyeda, who's my bleep
brother from another mother.
How long you been
doing your hair that way?
20 something years.
Seriously?
Well, you you have more claim
to fame on it than I do then.
Miss you, man.
Yeah, me too.
Hair looks good.
Video
Good, yeah?
A brother from another mother.
[laughs]
He always says that to me.
From Triple D, I sent people.
And then, I sent my friends.
Have they said hello?
Yes.
How many?
Hundreds.
GUY FIERI: I really
sent people that
are waiting for their flight.
And I'm like, seriously,
bounce out, go
over there, and get the oxtail.
I've heard from everybody.
The oxtails here are
the best on the island.
What makes them so awesome?
My mother's recipe.
My mom has a beautiful
sauce with it.
All right.
Let's hit it.
We're going to
just add the meat.
We'll start with cold water.
When it comes up to
a boil, it's done.
GUY FIERI: Then we'll
drain it, rinse it,
and then that's when
we start the process.
That's when we
start the process.
Got it.
GLENN UYEDA: First, we're going
to put in some dried dates,
dried orange peel, star
anise, raw peanuts.
Lot of work, man.
GLENN UYEDA: Dried
shitake, chicken and beef
stock, and as soon as it boils,
we're going to turn it down
to a simmer for three hours.
The sauce is the best
thing about the dish.
Seriously?
Daikon radish.
Making radish juice.
We're making radish juice.
GLENN UYEDA: We're going
to add the bulk in here.
Soy sauce.
GUY FIERI: I love soy sauce.
Lemon juice, fresh squeezed.
Sesame seed oil,
a key ingredient.
Red chili pepper.
To top it off, a little
toasted sesame seed.
Then we mixed it all up.
GUY FIERI: And this
is the sauce that we
did dip this whole thing in.
This is it.
We're going to finish the soup
with little Tennessee whiskey.
Here we go.
We're going to be
adding some baby
bok choy and the green onions.
O- M- G. This is crazy good.
What I can't get over is
the flavor in the broth
and then you get that mom sauce.
I'm shaking.
I can't get it in the spoon.
It's-- it's hot.
I want to shove it in my face.
I want to get in the bowl.
Guy came back the next
day to eat oxtail soup.
That's how much he
really enjoyed it.
You can just get away from me.
Argh.
[snarls]
How's the oxtail soup going?
Oxtail soup has gone
out of this world.
Every day is around
200 portions now.
Really?
Yes.
I dig it.
What did you bring me?
GLENN UYEDA: Tasty chicken.
Tasty chicken is our
number one seller.
This sauce is what makes it all.
So we're going to start it
with soy sauce and sugar.
Next ingredient is
garlic, red chilies.
We add a little heat to it.
Spicy salty, sweet.
This is our chicken
breading, and it's
corn starch and flour mixture.
And we're going to
put it on our chicken
and that's going to make
it fry nice and crispy.
Now that our chicken
it's finished,
we are going to dip
it in our sauce.
And it needs to be dipped hot.
If it's dipped cold, the
sauce won't stick to it.
Garnish it with
little green onions.
Tasty chicken up.
GUY FIERI: This
chicken is ridiculous.
This is killer.
There could be a
whole restaurant based
right off of tasty chicken.
It's like chicken crack.
Tasty chicken is definitely,
I suppose, like take on like
Hawaii-style fried chicken.
The crispiness of the
fried chicken and sort
of the sweet, savory
soy sauce dip.
It comes with like a soy,
garlic, a little bit of chili
flake.
It's like a sweet
and savory in one.
GUY FIERI: How's
the bowling alley?
Super good.
Did we get out all the alleys
and just make restaurant--
Yeah.
We we are this year.
And we're going to expand
the restaurant over.
GUY FIERI: Are you going
to still have bowling?
GLENN UYEDA: Yes.
- But just not as many?
Not as many.
More seating.
We have a two hour
waiting list on Friday,
Saturday, and Sunday.
Hold on.
[laughs]
You're telling me that
the funky little cafe--
GLENN UYEDA: Yes.
That service the bowling
alley has a waiting
list as a proper restaurant?
GLENN UYEDA: Yes.
Brother, man.
You go above and beyond.
Let's go to the hair.
What else you bring me?
This is spicy shrimp.
This is a popular dish as well.
So what goes on?
GLENN UYEDA:
Butterfly the shrimp
so it cooks a little faster.
We're going to be adding
the sambal sauce to it.
That has a lot of
ingredients, onions,
a lot of garlic, fresh
ginger, soy sauce.
This is a sweet soy called
Kecap sweet soy, oyster sauce.
This is sambal.
It has spicy,
chili, garlic in it.
Finish it with green onions.
Spicy shrimp up.
Mm-mm.
This is a fantastic dish.
That was great.
It's a little tang to it.
Just a little creamy.
Love it.
It's not too spicy.
A little bit of sweet.
Have like an oyster flavor.
Cleaned up my plate
pretty well, so it's
kind of a good indication
of how good it is.
If the bowling alleys
around the country
had this type of
food, there would
be a lot more people bowling.
Good job, brother.
- Thank you.
Keep it up.
I did the hair first by the way.
Just FYI.
This guy.
Not him, me.
I'm serious.
There are plenty of
alleys on the mainland
that could use those oxtails.
Call me buddy.
GUY FIERI: Now, coming up.
I could get a Food Network
on the moon with this thing.
A seafood spot in
Baltimore making
room for more family recipes.
That's how big it is?
GUY FIERI: And more family.
Hey, girls.
He's single by the way.
Sometimes I like to
go outside the box,
and sometimes I want to
hit up a place serving
up what the city is known for.
So in Baltimore, it's
all about the crab.
And this 45-year-old family
run restaurant I found
did not disappoint.
Since I was there in 2014,
the joint's gotten bigger
and so has the family.
This is Jimmy's Famous Seafood.
Seafood paella up.
Great food.
Great atmosphere.
You couldn't ask
for anything better.
Half and half soup.
It's always so
fresh, so innovative.
It's always going to be good.
I saw the episode of
Triple D and I was so proud
of everyone here at Jimmy's.
They're like family to us.
GUY FIERI: And
family to each other.
The joint was founded by
Jimmy Minadakis in 1974.
After he passed away, his sons,
Tony and John, and their mom
Oola, kept things going.
You're the chef?
Yes.
You're the manager,
front of the house?
And you're the boss?
- Backbone.
I know who the boss is.
Mhm.
When Triple D called,
I tohught it was surreal.
Never think it's going to happen
to you, because you're watching
that show two,
three times a week,
and now they want
you to be on it.
I can get Food Network on
the moon with this thing.
I'm not a doctor, but let
me take a look at that.
Come here, Rock.
You can take him.
Tony was the one
sweating bullets over here.
I'm going to go out on a limb
and say crab cake ingredients.
Yeah.
Now, whose recipe is this?
It's my father's.
We're gonna about 30 eggs,
give them a little whisk.
Next up, mayonnaise.
Whisk that up.
Our worcestershire sauce.
Worcestershire.
OK.
Black pepper.
Rock salt. House seasoning.
Dry mustard.
Wet mustard.
OK, next up?
Now we're ready to start
making the crab cakes.
So what goes first?
Little sauce.
Chopped breadcrumbs.
Parsley.
Crab meat.
This is 95% crab,
5% binding ingredient.
That's outrageous.
Now we're going
to make the crab
cakes into 8 ounce portions.
That's how big it is?
What is it, like,
crab meat loaf?
Pretty much.
Put our house seasoning on top,
and a little bit of butter.
How are we going to cook it?
350 degrees, about 15 minutes.
Here's our crab cake.
That's ridiculous.
Look at the size of that lump.
It doesn't need to be
dipped into anything.
I come to Maryland, I want the
bomb crab cakes, you delivered.
Thanks, bro.
The broiled crab cake.
Any time somebody is in
town, they're all coming in,
I saw Guy Fieri
eat at this place.
You gotta go there and
get the crab cakes.
Before the show, I'd say
we probably did about 1,000
pounds of crab meat a week.
Now we're probably
doing double that.
GUY FIERI: And it's not
just a one hit wonder.
That crab cake recipe is also
found in other menu options,
like Jimmy's oysters.
One of our better
sellers, for sure.
It was my dad's version of the
oyster Rockefeller, basically.
So to make our creamed
spinach, we start
by sweating down some onions.
We add the spinach, sautee it
a little bit, deglaze the pan
with some amaretto.
Then we add our cream, our
cheese, and a little bit
of slurry to thicken it up.
To make our Jimmy's
oysters, we start
with our freshly
shucked oysters,
topped with little old bay.
Creamed spinach.
Crab mixture.
A little more old bay.
Put it in the oven.
After those cook a little
bit, we put a little bit
of our imperial glaze on it.
It's basically our take
on the hollandaise.
Egg yolks, mayonnaise,
mustard, lemon juice,
and our crab seasoning.
Put it back in the oven
for a couple minutes,
and then we plate it.
Lemon.
Parsley.
Jimmy's oysters up.
They're absolutely fantastic.
These are more decadent because
of the crab imperial on top.
MAN: The oysters
are unbelievable.
It's the cheese, it's the
crab, it's the seasoning,
and it's also one
of those dishes
that when you see walk by your
table, and you point and say,
I want some of those sent
to my table right now.
What do you want to--
Oh, [mumbling].
- We have different options.
- What was that?
You're speaking in
tongues just now?
- We have different options--
- [mumbling]
GUY FIERI: But coming up,
there's no need to translate.
Gonna get in.
Because the food
speaks for itself.
Chef, how does it rate?
1 to 10?
10.
Be 11 if was 11 on a dial.
GUY FIERI: It's been
about five years
since I first popped
into Jimmy's Famous
Seafood, a Baltimore
institution that Jimmy
Minadakis opened in 1974.
40 years ago, your husband
Jimmy and the family lived here.
We're in the upstairs of Jimmy's
Famous, and downstairs was a--
It was a bar, a
lounge that he started.
We expanded, we built
the dining room.
GUY FIERI: And when
he passed away,
his sons kept growing
their dad's dream.
Two bars, two banquet halls.
Now we got the food trucks.
You know, sky's the limit.
GUY FIERI: And a far cry from
the low hanging, head banging
setup they had before.
Could you please
stand up straight?
You're driving me crazy.
- Sorry.
I'm gonna-- yeah.
You're the tallest
guy in the shortest hood
that they have in Baltimore.
When we first filmed Triple
D, we had a special guest
and we could barely,
all three, fit
behind the line at that point.
This is my executive chef from
Johnny Garlic's in California,
Chef Jeff Poetzel.
Now, Jeff is from this area.
I had to get in on it.
OK, give us the rundown.
Soft shell crab sandwich.
[whistle]
It's like meat dancing.
We gotta do a little cleaning?
Yep.
- And that's all she wrote.
- That's it.
What's the next step?
Just a simple
dredge and pan fry.
Two minutes on each side.
Nice, crispy, golden brown.
Put the crab right on there.
Little Chesepeake mustard
to finish it off again.
Gonna get in.
Here we go.
All right.
Mm.
Wow.
The crab is so fresh,
the batter is so light.
Jeff, how does it rate?
1 to 10?
10.
Be an 11 if there
was 11 on a dial.
GUY FIERI: They're
also cranking up a mash
up of a couple local legends.
We're basically taking the
two iconic Maryland soups--
Maryland crab soup and
cream of crab soup,
and we combine it into one dish.
Well, Maryland crab soup
is a tomato based version.
We start our mirepoix,
sweat it down,
get our seasonings in there.
Old bay, worcestershire,
crushed tomato, tomato
paste, chicken base, crab base.
And then a little water.
Let it reduce a little
bit, and then we're
going to add our mixed
veggies, fresh potatoes,
and our crab meat.
Now we're going to
make our cream of crab,
similar to a clam chowder.
Take cream, crab base,
old bay, and sherry wine.
Heat it up, then we're going
to take a blended mirepoix.
We sweat it down with old bay,
sherry, a little bit of crab
base, and then we're
going to incorporate that
into that cream based mixture.
We're going to finish
it with our roux,
and of course our
crab meat at the end,
to keep those
lumps nice and big.
Take our Maryland crab first,
top it with our cream of crab,
and then we finish it off with
a crab stencil of old bay.
Half and half soup.
You get a Maryland crab soup
taste, topped off with, like,
a milkiness, sweet sensation.
Unbelievable.
I like them equally
separate, but together
it's just, like, so good.
Delicious.
How proud is your dad?
I hope he's very proud.
Very proud.
Every parent's dream
is to have their kids
have a better life
than they did,
and because of my dad sacrifice
and, obviously, because
of this show, we're that.
Hey, girls, he's
single, by the way.
He's the heir to the
empire of the, uh--
Jimmy's Famous
Seafood crab cake.
So after Triple D aired,
literally that summer,
I met my wife.
Got a two-year-old daughter now.
Triple D helped
me find love, too.
At the premiere party,
I met my fiance.
A lot of family love,
a lot of family respect.
You guys are doing
a phenomenal job.
Congrats.
Thank you.
And those guys are still
working right beside their mom,
keeping Jimmy's legacy
and recipes going.
Now coming up--
My mom's named Penny.
A pizza slinging sister--
GUY FIERI: Spicing things
up with a Santa Fe staple.
Green chili makes it.
GUY FIERI: Now, back in 2009 I
hit up this joint in New Mexico
where the chef was spinning
pies with some real deal
Santa Fe flavor.
These days she's turned out
more seating, a bigger menu,
and is wheeling that
dough all over town.
This is back road pizza.
Chili beef for Leo.
Back Roads has become sort
of an institution in Santa Fe.
Here's the local.
I do come here to Back Roads
fairly often because if you
don't, you miss something new.
GUY FIERI: That's because
Chef Piper Kapin made a name
for herself pulling
all kinds of piping
hot pies out of the oven.
Now, I'm going to
tell you right now
that I think that we're
dealing with, like,
a real pizza maniac, OK?
And I'll tell you how.
See that?
That's pizza maniac right there.
Huh?
Reaching in the deck.
Getting in the way back.
Catching it on the arm.
Why do you think
I wear wristbands?
And back in '09, come to find
out she's a sister from--
the same mother?
My mom's named Penny.
We talked back and forth
about our moms a little bit,
and then decided that we
should get them on the phone.
Race to the Penny.
PENNY: Hello?
Oh, she got her Penny first.
Hey, Penny.
This is Guy Fieri from
"Diners, Drive Ins, and Dives."
How are you?
PENNY: I'm fine.
My mom's name is penny.
[laughter]
I was very happy
to be included.
You should be
very proud of her.
PENNY: Thank you.
And we are very proud.
I'm just a proud mom.
What can I say?
And my mom still talks
about it to this day.
[laughter]
GUY FIERI: But it's
Piper's pies that
are the real talk of the town.
One of the best things about
the pizza here at Back Road
is the crust.
Start with water, dry yeast.
Extra virgin olive oil?
Yes.
- Now, on the flour--
- Yes?
- High gluten.
Salt.
And a little bit of sugar.
Now, this is going to
run for 15, 20 minutes.
This looks like a pillow
fight with one aluminum bat.
Cover it up for
about 15 minutes.
Wow.
Look at how that proofed up.
Get me a picture next to it.
About 13 ounces of dough.
Now, look at this
little technique
you have that it's
spinning for you.
Mhm.
How are you-- are you
applying more pressure
on the right side than--
- Yes.
A little bit more.
Goes around.
Do you see that?
First cornmeal.
This goes right on here.
Olive oil.
Just to brown it up nicely.
Yep.
Little sesame seeds.
On every pizza?
Yep.
I don't think I've
seen that before.
Let's make the one
with the green chilies.
- The Mexican?
- Yeah.
All right.
Sauce.
Mozzarella cheese.
Red onions.
- Nice sprinkling.
Yep.
Green chili.
There we go.
- That's it.
- Pepperoni.
Oh, pepperoni.
OK.
So we pop that bad boy down.
You're up?
Yeah.
[whistle]
It is.
So hot.
- I'm going to go over here.
Yeah.
[music playing]
Mm.
You know what?
I gotta have more pizza
with green chilies on it.
That rocks.
And I'm in luck with
this new regional recipe.
That's called the local.
We use that pizza to spotlight
local ingredients in Santa Fe.
Our pizza sauce.
New Mexico green chili.
New Mexico roasted red potatoes.
Homemade sausage, which
is local New Mexico pork.
Cheddar cheese curds.
They have a great
flavor and texture.
They're a little different
than typical pizza cheese.
Now it's ready to
go in the oven.
For about 7 and 1/2 minutes.
535 degrees.
The local for Kim.
It's cheese curds.
I love cheese curds.
They're way better
than regular cheese.
Never had potatoes on pizza, but
this was really, really unique.
The green chili on there
just has a bit of a kick.
Delicious.
GUY FIERI: People in Santa Fe
don't get too much green chili?
I mean, they're not,
like, green chili'd out?
I don't know anyone
that's green chili'd out.
- Really?
- You crave it.
Like, when you're
gone from Santa Fe,
you want green chili as
soon as you get back.
It's really a cornerstone
of New Mexican cuisine.
GUY FIERI: So much
so that it's not even
covering the crust anymore.
We're making our green
chili chicken soup.
We're going to start by
seasoning the chicken.
Salt, black pepper, oregano,
basil, minced garlic.
We roast this in
our pizza ovens.
12 minutes at 535 degrees.
We are going to
assemble our soup.
Start by melting butter and
sautee-ing yellow onions.
Add flour.
Get the roux started.
Chicken broth.
Mushrooms.
Green chili.
Roasted chicken.
We're gonna give that a stir.
Add the second
half of the broth.
Nutmeg.
Cream.
We're going to
serve this with two
pieces of warm French bread.
Green chili soup for table 23.
Green chili chicken soup.
The soup is so flavorful.
It's got a really good kick.
The chicken is really fresh.
It is so good.
Oh, yeah! (IMITATING
ARNOLD SCHWARZENEGGER)
Here at the pizza gym.
I wind it up.
This side here is working
to there, and down here.
That's what does it all.
[laughter]
The Triple D fans are some
of the best fans out there.
We're busier than ever.
We've put as much seating
in here as we can fit.
Expanded the patio.
We decided to get a food truck.
Slice of cheese for Bird.
It's just a way for us to expand
a little bit without getting
another brick and mortar.
Thank you.
I'm a new parent.
I have a son named Leo.
We're continuing to grow each
year, so just stay the course.
That's what I'm talking about.
Talk to our pennies.
That's right.
They taught us well.
My mom's a real Penny.
Just goes to show you
these Triple D places
really are just like family.
Like Piper, whose
pizzas are still
making her mom
proud in Santa Fe,
the Baltimore Minadakis
brothers and their mom
still cranking out dad's
killer crab recipes.
And my brother from
another mother, Glen,
in Honolulu, whose
bowley alley eats
are the perfect way to roll.
We'll keep shaking the
Triple D family tree
next time on Triple D Nation.
Get your lean, OK?
Gotta get your arms up, so
it doesn't run your elbows.
Called the hunch.
OK.
Relax the neck.
Pat me down, Mick.
There we go.