Hey, everybody, I'm Guy
Fieri, and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip--
It's like shake and bake.
Yeah.
The Camaro's taking a
detour-- a where, with, what--
to joints a little
off the beaten path.
I want more of that all day.
Like East Coast Canadian
cuisine in Ottawa--
this is a handful right here--
one-of-a-kind
sandwiches in Reno--
look at this-- and
a righteous spot
in Richmond, Virginia--
it is so delicious--
serving a one-way ticket
to Jamaica, "mon."
This is the dish that
should be torturing you.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
[theme music]
And I got to be honest with
you, before "Triple D,"
I can't say that I had a lot
of curried goat or oxtails,
or Jamaican food
for that matter.
I mean, not out
on the West Coast,
but once I got a taste for
it, oh, I have been hooked.
So I'm right outside
of Richmond, Virginia,
in Chesterfield, to check
out a joint everybody's
talking about, and they're
serving up my favorites.
This is Carena's
Jamaican Grille.
[vibrant music]
Gonna need some goat.
Carena has put Jamaica right
in the heart of Richmond.
Shrimp Rundown
with rice and peas.
I am addicted.
GUY FIERI: And he's not
the only one hooked.
After Carena Ives started
serving the food she grew up
with at her first spot in '94--
Pick up, let's go!
GUY FIERI: --she felt
the demand to expand
into this joint in 2007.
Customers kept begging
for a bigger location.
I just had a gentleman
stop me in the parking lot,
and he says, oh man, I
love going to that place,
and it's packed, and
the food's so great.
Carena's does a great
job with her stewed dishes,
especially the oxtail.
Oxtail lunch.
You can't come to
a Jamaican restaurant
without trying the oxtail.
It is the bomb.
This isn't from an ox.
It's from a cow.
- It's the best part.
What are we gonna do with it?
We start our marinade.
Scotch bonnet peppers--
GUY FIERI: Got it.
--and yellow onions,
and then this is a little
bit of adobo, thyme, garlic, and
a little bit of Worcestershire.
And how long is
this gonna marinate?
For about 24 hours.
Vegetable oil goes
in our pan here,
but we're gonna sear it off.
GUY FIERI: And what are
we gonna braise it in?
CARENA IVES: Plain water.
Water is gonna make the
foundation of this oxtail?
Yes.
Huh.
About how long is
this gonna go for?
About two hours.
Here we go.
It's been doing its thing.
We're nice and tender.
GUY FIERI: OK.
A little bit more
onions and peppers go in,
scallions, and a little
bit more Scotch bonnet.
And I'm not gonna
go all the way.
Oh, go all the
way, it's you and me
All right.
And some stewed tomatoes.
GUY FIERI: And where
did you learn all this?
- My mother.
- I love it.
Thyme and a little
bit more adobo.
We'll let it simmer
for about 20 minutes,
then we'll add slurry,
flour and water.
GUY FIERI: So what's
going on with the beans?
Those are butter beans.
Smells fantastic.
Mmm.
CARENA IVES: That's it.
OK, we get into
the rice and beans?
Yes.
Small red beans, water to
cover, bay leaf, a little bit
of onion, allspice.
This is sort of the
big component of jerk.
Thyme and garlic.
GUY FIERI: We're just
gonna keep adding stuff?
Oh yeah, and you know
what else we need to do?
Towel, kitchen towel
needs to go in.
Then we're gonna
also build the rice?
CARENA IVES: Coconut
milk goes in.
This is what's gonna give it
its nice, creamy richness.
A little bit more thyme--
Boy, this thyme is taking up--
Yes, some thyme.
--a lot of time.
CARENA IVES: And some scallion.
Just big ol' massive
pieces like that?
Yes.
These are Scotch bonnets,
and we'll just break it open.
- OK, good.
- Put that in there.
Rice.
Is there any
measurement going on?
Oh, why?
This is just pour, dump, add?
CARENA IVES: You kind of feel.
Oh yeah, that's
how I always do it.
So this is gonna cook down?
CARENA IVES: And then
we're gonna plate.
And here comes your tail.
GUY FIERI: So a nice
little gravy, beans.
Now, is it proper to pick it
up and eat it with your hands?
The best way to do it.
This is the dish right now
that should be torturing you.
It is so delicious.
You get the tenderness, but
the chew, of the oxtail.
It's luscious.
It's tangy.
It's meaty.
Just soaking up all that
gravy, all that sauce.
That slow-mo is for you.
Got oxtail with rice and peas.
The flavor and the tenderness
is right on the money.
I suck the meat off the bone.
It's that good.
Fantastic.
I can't give it a better word.
GUY FIERI: The killer is
the rice and peas on there.
I want more of that all day.
Tremendous.
Whole Red Snapper Escoveitch.
Pick up!
Are you from Jamaica?
Born and bred.
Is this a good representation
of Jamaican food?
Absolutely.
CUSTOMER: In Jamaica, we
like the hot, the curry
that we have, the jerk.
Those are like bold flavors.
We are bold people.
We love adding ginger to
our juices, to our seasonings.
Island Fried on the line!
I love the Island
Fried Chicken, mostly
because of the ginger gravy.
You can't get it anywhere else.
We're doing
another gravy thing?
Yes, because the rice--
It's not swimsuit season.
It's not swimsuits--
--loves gravy.
We start with the
garlic, black pepper,
salt, onion powder, rosemary,
cayenne for a little kick.
Dry rub this on the chicken.
How long is this gonna set up?
24 hours, so they can get to
know each other, be roommates.
Been In the kitchen a
little too long there, sister.
I know.
Starting to talk
to the chicken.
I know.
Dredge them in flour,
salt, and pepper.
A whole breast and a
whole thigh and drum?
CARENA IVES: And it goes into
our fryer for about 20 minutes.
GUY FIERI: Got it.
So we're gonna
make this gravy.
A little bit of oil goes in,
garlic, some sliced onion,
stewed tomatoes.
A lot of ginger.
The brown sugar,
thyme, and bay leaf.
Now, you house-make
the chicken stock?
Yes.
When do the Scotch
bonnets go in?
Put them in right now.
Simmer for about 45 minutes,
and then we strain it.
Tighten it up with a little
bit of slurry and butter.
GUY FIERI: OK.
We don't just give you a
big ol' breast like that.
Hiyah.
Put some cuts in it for you.
Yep.
CARENA IVES: And
on the plate here.
GUY FIERI: There you go.
And here comes
the magic sauce.
Ginger-tomato gravy.
CARENA IVES: Have at it.
[vibrant music]
That gravy could
go on anything.
If there was one thing I would
be bottling and selling--
CARENA IVES: Gravy.
It's like something
I've never had.
It is dynamite.
And this is one of my
all-time faves now.
Island Fried Chicken
with sweet ginger gravy.
It's a little crispy, but not
soggy, and so it is just right.
And that sweet
with the gingery?
To die for.
Wow, what an adventure.
This is the cheapest flight
to Jamaica I've ever had.
Two goat lunches,
hot and ready.
If you come once,
you're gonna come again,
and you're gonna love all of it.
GUY FIERI: You are the
Jamaican ambassador.
I'm gonna get you
little flags to put
out in front of your car.
- All right.
- Thank you, my friend.
- Thanks for coming.
Outstanding.
What is over here?
Um.
[laughs]
GUY FIERI: Up next, we're
headed to Ottawa, Canada-- dude,
this looks awesome-- to
check out specialities
from a Newfoundland chef--
razzmatazz and pizzazz--
including a recipe
passed down for centuries.
It tastes pretty fresh
for a recipe that old.
That's exactly
what I was gonna say.
[theme music]
I'm here in downtown
Ottawa, Canada,
about a five-minute walk
from the Parliament,
to check out a restaurant where
a chef from Newfoundland-- now,
hang on a second.
I've never said Ottawa,
Newfoundland, or Parliament,
in a "Triple D" show.
Anyhow, I'm here to
check out a joint
where this guy's taking street
food to an artisan level.
This is OCCO.
Poutine hitting the pass.
When I tried the food the
first time, I was hooked.
So I've got the
cauliflower wings.
There's a lot of
East Coast flavors
from the East Coast of Canada.
GUY FIERI: That's
because Chef Mark
Steele is from Newfoundland.
He went from corporate cooking
to catering to this joint.
What does OCCO mean?
Orleans Catering Companies.
GUY FIERI: Orleans
is an area here?
It's the east end of Ottawa.
We take very approachable
food everybody likes,
but we make things from scratch,
use the local ingredients.
CUSTOMER: You get the
burgers and the fries,
but then you get
the specialty things
like the East Coast Donair.
GUY FIERI: Which is a
familiar regional dish.
CUSTOMER: It's
ground beef that's
piled together on a pita bread.
GUY FIERI: Fired up with
Mark's own culinary punch.
CUSTOMER: The combination of the
sweet sauce and the hot peppers
is so, so good.
All right, so what
are we getting into?
An East Coast Donair.
A where, with, what?
MARK STEELE: It's a spin on
a gyro made with ground beef.
Now, this is our version.
A little more pizzazz,
more razzmatazz.
Razzmatazz and pizzazz.
What did I get into?
We have some ground chuck,
about 70/30, garlic powder,
onion powder, smoked
paprika pepper, salt.
This is the pizzazz
here, cayenne.
Pizzazz.
Then to the meat,
fresh oregano.
Throw this right on
the sheet pan here.
Just roll that out.
Throw it in the oven, 350
for about seven minutes.
Now, the donair is
something that you
find throughout Canada?
Especially the East Coast.
But this sauce is
what differentiates
it from any other beef, meat
sandwich-type sliced thing.
You got it, absolutely.
We start off with evaporated
milk, sweetened condensed milk.
Those cows are
rich and thick here.
MARK STEELE: Fresh garlic.
Because that's what I always
do-- evaporated milk, sweetened
condensed milk, garlic.
Some sugar.
I'm just gonna add
in the vinegar,
and you're gonna
see this thicken.
Vinegar's gonna
tighten this up?
MARK STEELE: Big time.
This Is where the magic happens.
It's already starting
to thicken up.
I've never seen this.
What do you think
has happened here?
Beautiful.
Can we call Alton
brown right now?
This is an Alton
Brown question 101.
We've got the meat cooked off.
Take it to the flat top.
MARK STEELE: Grill the pita.
Hit this with some
garlic butter.
GUY FIERI: Dude,
this looks awesome.
Nice and thin and easy going.
A little cheddar, crisp
lettuce, and a ton of sauce.
And then some cherry tomatoes,
sweet mini peppers, and sliced
jalape o, and some more cheese.
Finish it with our
pickled red onion.
And there you go.
Look at that.
Yeah, don't you know.
Oh, you got a little--
that's the way it
should be, though.
Oh, you bring a
bath towel, or have
a car wash when people leave.
They can--
- Exactly.
- --just walk through it.
Get hosed down.
GUY FIERI: Delicious, chef.
The meat is what's the most
impressive, with the seasoning,
with the crust, with
the caramelization.
But when you get the
fresh vegetables mixed
with the cheese, and then
you get the little kiss
of the sauce, it rounds it out.
That is really good.
Donair in the pass.
The best one I've ever had.
Seriously?
The meat is nice and juicy.
It's perfect.
Where is my sweet sauce?
No, you can't have
any more sweet sauce.
This is bang-on exactly
what I've had down east.
And you've got to
be from Newfoundland.
That beard and stuff.
I mean--
No, I just married
a Newfoundlander.
You married up, my friend.
OCCO hits home with the
fish and chips, the chowder
on the menu, the cod cakes.
Cod cakes, table 16.
This is grandma level.
I've never had a cod cake like
hers until I tried Mark's.
There's a secret
recipe I heard,
and you can't have
it anywhere else.
Newfoundland Cod Cake recipe.
This recipe is 432 years old.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Where does the 32 come in?
Because when it was handed
off to me, it was for 400 years
old.
And I'm gonna cook
the potatoes--
Yukon potatoes.
--with a parsnip
and the onion.
Poach our cod separately.
Newfoundland, man, where
I grew up, cod is king.
In cod we trust.
Do not take our
American slogan
and rip it off and throw a
fish in the middle of it.
Oh, I thought you
guys stole that from us.
- Do you have it on a coin?
- Uh--
- Thank you.
- I think we might.
- Thank you!
You don't have it on a coin!
MARK STEELE: We're gonna
add our cod to our potatoes
and melt the butter.
This here is
Newfoundland savory.
It has a very unique flavor,
and it's less woodier
than, say, a winter savory.
I was just gonna say that.
This is one of the
magic ingredients.
Add salt and pepper,
fresh parsley.
I mash this up.
GUY FIERI: All right,
so these will set up.
Then we're gonna bread them
using seasoned flour, egg
wash, and panko bread crumbs.
Drop them in the fryer
for four minutes.
And what do we
serve them with?
It's caper berry mayo.
This I got to see.
That's the big caper berry,
seed pods inside of it,
and it comes in
a picklely brine.
Give these just a quick chop.
And then I'm gonna throw in
all of my ingredients, mayo--
You sure that's not
sweetened condensed milk again?
Yeah.
[laughs] Dijon,
it's local honey,
and lemon juice, flat
leaf Italian parsley,
fresh dill, chives, and thyme.
And a little "warshed"
Worcestershire.
That's how you get
around saying it wrong.
Pepper, salt, add
a little lemon zest.
We give this a quick puree.
So this is gonna be
our cod cake plate--
the caper berry mayo we
just made, red cabbage slaw,
the jalape os, cherry tomatoes.
You should have wore
a helmet for this one.
This one's gonna blow your mind.
OK, fried Atlantic cod
cakes, some fresh herb,
caper berries, lemon wedge.
And it's done.
This is gonna be interesting.
It's dynamite.
It's creamy, delicate.
A nice amount of crunch
to the outside of it.
It's like a fish
and chip gnocchi.
You can taste the
fish, but not fishy.
And the caper aiole
is the sleeper here.
That extra acidity
and razzmatazz is
what elevates the entire game.
It tastes pretty fresh
for a recipe that old.
Exactly what I was gonna say.
Cod cakes.
The panko breading that's
on them, super crispy.
The sauce makes it perfect.
I think it's a
200-year-old recipe.
I'm new here, but I'm
gonna have to correct you.
What is it, Mark,
422 year and 30 days?
We're looking at 33, I think.
Today, it's 33.
We're just-- just keep
clicking them off the board.
CUSTOMER: If you're looking for
a good place to eat in Ottawa,
OCCO Kitchen's the
place to go to.
This is a handful right here.
O-C-C-O?
O-C-C-O.
O-C-C-O, later.
Up next, a funky deli
in Reno, Nevada--
they make really
weird sandwiches--
pushing breakfast burrito
boundaries-- can you help me
lift it up?
[groans]---- and going off
the chain with the chicken.
This is the kind of stuff
that we used to make
up when we were in college.
[theme music]
So I'm just like you guys.
I mean, not just for "Triple D,"
but for me and for my family.
I'm always looking
for great restaurants.
I'm always on the hunt.
So a few years ago, I was
in Truckee, California.
Everybody tells me
about this place,
you got to get
the sandwich here.
So I did, and it was dynamite.
Well, now, I'm in Reno, Nevada,
and I find out these dudes
have got a second location.
I got to check it out.
This is Full Belly Deli.
The Philly and on Parmesan.
Absolutely lives
up to its name.
Definitely, full belly.
TOM MARRIN: The Cheesesteak
with blue cheese
bread, one of my favorites.
These guys are all about
creating a great sandwich.
They're passionate about it.
GUY FIERI: But it was passion
for the slopes that led Eric
Barton and Tom Marrin
to Tahoe, where
they opened their first
joint in nearby Truckee.
And we just kind of saw a
niche that needed to be filled.
I love making sandwiches.
He loved eating sandwiches.
- It's like shake and bake.
- Yeah.
GUY FIERI: We're in Truckee.
We're doing this
family road trip,
and every time I would say
to somebody, where do we eat?
They would go, well, you got
to go to Full Belly Deli.
I go there, and it's
not your average deli.
They make really
weird sandwiches, OK?
And they're doubling down at
their second location here
in Reno.
We got our biscuits
and gravy burrito.
Their biscuits and
gravy breakfast burrito
is like two breakfasts in one.
They have the biscuit and
the home-fried potato in there.
If you're looking for
all your breakfasts,
just come get this burrito.
Let's see it,
what's the game plan?
TOM MARRIN: We're
making a chorizo sausage
gravy for our burrito.
Olive oil--
And you're making the chorizo?
It's made from a local
company here in town.
Got it.
TOM MARRIN: Breakfast
sausage, all pork.
Once the meat's
cooked down, I add
organic AP flour,
paprika, granulated
garlic, onion powder.
Cook that flour out.
Half and half and whole milk.
Let this come to a simmer
and salt and pepper,
and it'll be ready to serve.
This next step of making
biscuits for one dish, it's
impressive.
Organic AP flour here, sugar,
baking soda, baking powder.
Just give this a
quick pulse here.
Then we have our
extra cold butter.
Give it a good pulse to
get it about pea size.
The idea is breaking
that butter up,
so it just sits there
suspended between the flour.
So when it cooks, you really
develop all of those layers.
Correct.
It means everything in the
world of making a good biscuit.
TOM MARRIN: Incorporate
the buttermilk slowly.
And it's gonna kind
of look a little dry--
But he's got more butter
than we typically see.
So this is gonna make a nice,
light, flaky biscuit if we
can get it to stay together.
Because right now, it just
looks like we're trying to make
a sandcastle out of dry sand.
TOM MARRIN: So we're
going for a square here.
Could be a triangle
for all I care.
TOM MARRIN: Roll this out.
We're gonna cut this.
You brush it with a
little bit of buttermilk?
We're gonna finish
with salt and pepper.
GUY FIERI: OK.
We go in the oven how long?
TOM MARRIN: 25 minutes at 350.
So--
That is beautiful, wow.
Drop the tortilla on the
flat top to warm it up.
Hash brown coming out
of the fryer there.
Gonna take our biscuit,
slice this up--
Oh!
Seems sacrilegious.
TOM MARRIN: We're gonna
add a little cheddar
cheese to this guy, a crispy
hash brown, biscuit there.
And then we've got gravy.
GUY FIERI: Oh, so it's for
the whole family, I see.
TOM MARRIN: We roll it up.
Can you help me lift it up?
[groans] That's ridiculous.
TOM MARRIN: We're gonna take
that over to the panini press,
and then we are ready to go.
High carb, meet carb.
[vibrant music]
Well, I'm gonna tell you,
first thing, as scared of it
as I was, for some
reason, the way you've
made it, the way
you've seasoned it,
it really is not overly heavy.
It's delicious.
The biscuit is light
and flaky in there.
The crunch of the hash
brown inside is really nice.
But the kicker for
me is the gravy, bro.
I could just have
a bowl of gravy.
This is a ski bum delight 101.
Well done, man.
Yeah, thank you very
much, appreciate it.
Well done.
We got a biscuits
and gravy burrito.
It blows my expectations
out of the water.
The chorizo and the
gravy has so much flavor.
The biscuit is
soft and delicious.
Unbelievable.
Dirka Dirka, Dirka on
jalape o cheddar bread.
Your favorite
sandwich on the menu?
Dirka Dirka, baby.
You get that big crunchy
bite with that slaw.
You got that spicy
something in there.
You're gonna love me for telling
you to get the Dirka Dirka.
They sell Dirka
Dirka T-shirts.
The word's gotten out.
So everybody knows about the
Dirka Dirka and the Philly
and the GNAR Burrito.
There's really a lot
of options for everybody.
When I went and tried you
guys for the first time,
and I find that you guys
had a place in Reno,
you haven't let me down.
That's two for two.
Let's see what's up next.
And we got a spoiler alert.
It turns out, the
third time is a charm.
Oh, how cute.
He took chips and they
put it around the chicken.
Dude.
Huh?
We good?
Got to go get the
pressure washer?
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging
out at Full Belly
Deli in Truckee, Californ--
[audio screeches]
Sorry, Reno, Nevada.
He's got one in Truckee.
He's got one in Reno.
This is the new one.
I found these guys
a couple of years
ago in Truckee on a
big family road trip.
We're talking about scratch-made
sandwiches, funky creations.
Nacho Pollo Loco
in the window.
The Nacho Pollo Loco
sandwich is ridiculous.
The chicken itself is breaded
with the nacho cheese chips.
You don't find
this anywhere else.
It's really delicious.
Now we're gonna get into
a chicken sandwich that's
coated in nacho cheese chips.
This is the kind of stuff
that we used to make
up when we were in college.
When you would have the
leftover potato chips that
were just the crumbles
at the bottom,
I would always
incorporate those.
TOM MARRIN: First, we're gonna
season the egg wash here.
We've got some hot sauce, kosher
salt, fresh cracked pepper.
Do a quick whisk on that.
All natural chicken breast.
A little dredge
there for the flour.
Into our seasoned egg wash.
Then we're gonna pack
those chips on there.
You want to get
that crunch, and you
want to get that flavor.
Now we're gonna let these rest
a bit before you fry them?
We don't fry
them, we bake them.
GUY FIERI: Oh,
we're gonna bake it?
It's healthy.
I mean, come on.
See?
Just when you think
they weren't gonna
let you be healthy at
the Full Belly Deli,
they go ahead and
bake the chicken.
TOM MARRIN: Yeah,
we bake the chicken.
Next step?
The southwest sauce.
We're gonna add our chipotles
and adobo, fresh cilantro.
GUY FIERI: Gonna be a
little heat in that.
Mayonnaise, sour
cream, then we're
gonna add the chipotle
and cilantro mixture.
I just got a huge waft of
that smoky, dry, chipotle.
Very interesting.
I'll hold this, your honor.
OK.
Horseradish, lemon
juice, salt, pepper.
Finish it off.
- OK.
Pickles are next.
Got it.
This is an immersion circulator?
TOM MARRIN: Yes.
Well, isn't that just
the cutest little thing?
We have a fountain
like that in our room.
I could also be
brining my pickles.
We've got white vinegar
here, sugar, and salt.
And that'll be our
brining liquid.
And we're gonna go a
whole yellow mustard seed,
toasted caraway seed
here, peppercorns.
GUY FIERI: Tricolor?
TOM MARRIN: Yep.
Whole garlic, bay leaf, an
arbol chili, fresh dill.
Then we're gonna add
our pickling cucumbers.
GUY FIERI: OK.
TOM MARRIN: Then
we have our brine.
How long are we
gonna sous vide?
TOM MARRIN: 2 and 1/2 hours--
GUY FIERI: Really?
TOM MARRIN: --at 140--
Could you use some really
good sous vide terminology?
Let's go 39.9.
There you go.
For two hours and 41 minutes.
And--
And they'll be done.
TOM MARRIN: Then we
let them sit overnight.
Look at this.
Can I just come in and buy this?
TOM MARRIN: Yes.
Yes, you can.
Good, I'll take this.
So jalape os and a
bunch of cheddar.
TOM MARRIN: We toast it up.
And we've got our
southwest sauce.
Romaine lettuce and
heirloom tomatoes, a pickle.
GUY FIERI: I like
where we're going.
Nacho-crusted chicken breast.
Fold it over.
GUY FIERI: Dude.
Bread is dynamite.
It's got a good texture,
good chew, but not heavy.
I love the cheese and the
jalape os on the outside.
And the chicken breast, it's
got a really good crunch.
I mean, I heard it when
you hit it with the knife.
Awesome smokiness out
of the southwest sauce.
But the kicker that refreshes it
is that pickle, and that pickle
sings.
Singing pickles.
Nacho Pollo and
jalape o coming in.
The chicken is real
juicy, real tender,
but the chips add
like a perfect crunch.
The pickles are amazing,
nothing like any pickles
I've ever had.
The jalape o cheddar bread
is definitely the way to go,
spicy, but cheesy.
Cheesesteak on blue cheese.
It's a 25-pound deli.
Once they moved to Reno,
I gained 25 pounds.
Line of the year.
Good night.
If you're looking
for a great sandwich,
I would say this is
the best place to come.
And you're gonna
leave with a full belly.
Great sandwich, great
attitude, great creativity.
Dynamite.
Just gave me goose bumps.
Gonna put them on
the menu next week.
Come on down, Full Belly Deli.
Sous vide goose bumps.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry, there's
plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
I'm spoiled.
I know.
I can tell.
You have more bling than me.
We have a rule.
You can't have more
bling than the host.
[laughter, theme music]