I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow.
...we're digging into all kinds
of barbecue goodness...
Oh, what a great idea.
...like spicy sausage
in Virginia...
Aren't you the gangster?
...crazy chicken in Canada...
You are in the business
of chicken,
and business is good.
...and brisket in Vermont...
I'll give you
some props, man.
...served up in a bowl.
Oh!
You guys are still here?
I was having a shovel fest.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here in the Hintonburg
area of Ottawa, Canada,
which is not too far
from downtown,
to check out
a family-run chicken joint,
which brings me
to that childhood riddle.
Why did the chicken
cross the road?
Hey, guess what?
I think I figured it out.
This is The Foolish Chicken.
Saucing up two more
half chickens.
It's a fun place to go to.
It's always tasty.
Does the name fit
the restaurant --
Foolish Chicken?
You got to be foolish
to not come here.
FIERI: And Rick Boland
and Natalie Aucoin
were no chickens when it came to
jumping into this joint.
FIERI:
How did it start?
My aunt and uncle had
a chicken-and-rib place.
I worked for them.
But he wanted to open
his own place,
and I was
an interior designer.
So I said, "Okay, let's find
some place. Let's renovate it."
And what kind of
chicken joint are we?
It's pretty classic
rotisserie-style chicken.
In this area specifically,
I think it's cool
because we're, like,
one of the only restaurants...
-That does it.
-...that does it, yeah.
One half rotisserie chicken up!
WOMAN: This chicken actually
tastes the way
I remember chicken tasting
when I was a kid.
-What are we making?
-We're making chicken rub.
Brown sugar, paprika,
salt, parsley,
basil, oregano,
and thyme...
Got it.
...onion powder,
garlic powder,
allspice, and cinnamon.
Wow. We're all over
the board here.
Exactly.
You didn't know that
you were gonna be
in the restaurant business.
It's amazing
where life leads you.
Tell me. I'm standing in
a tiny, little kitchen
in the middle of Ottawa
talking to an interior designer
that's making chicken.
Yep. Olive oil,
Worcester sauce.
Rub our chickens.
Really? That's as simple
as it is right there.
It is.
What kind of rotisserie?
Where is it?
It's right behind you.
The whole restaurant
is based off
of the Henny Penny
Rotisserie Deluxe?
It is.
That is old-school
right there.
What temperature
do we cook at?
350, about an hour,
an hour 10.
What are we gonna
work on next?
Our chicken
barbecue sauce.
Ketchup, molasses...
Molasses.
...liquid smoke,
soy sauce, honey...
Red wine vinegar.
-Yes. Chopped garlic...
-Right.
...lemon juice,
salt and pepper.
Cook down a little bit.
What are we on to?
-Cornbread.
-Make it in house?
Yeah. I start with eggs,
brown sugar.
Whisk it.
Canola oil,
creamed corn,
sour cream,
green chilies, cornmeal.
So you have to fold
the dry ingredients in.
Oh, that's what
we're doing now.
Baking powder and salt.
And how long are we
gonna bake this?
-20 minutes.
-Our beautiful cornbread's done.
-Yes.
-Ta-da!
I definitely like
the end piece.
Oh, that's good.
We had cornbread in Hawaii
at Fat Daddy's.
That is
that level of cornbread.
Mmm! Let's talk about
the chicken.
Why don't you help me?
Oh, you're the best.
Cut this in half
and onto the grill.
Throw some barbecue sauce
on there.
Couple of minutes
on either side.
The plate looks
a little naked.
Let me get you
some more cornbread.
Oh, what a great idea!
I don't like
to overdo it.
There we are.
[ Laughs ]
Cornbread is on point.
It's really good.
Rotisserie is just the lost art
of enjoying chicken.
Self-basting as it cooks.
Super juicy,
lightly seasoned.
The barbecue sauce complements
it really nicely.
That's real-deal chicken.
You are in the business
of chicken,
and business is good.
So, I have a half chicken
with fries.
That's very juicy and flavorful.
I love the crispiness
of the skin.
The sauce they use
is just out of this world.
I didn't know that
Crosby, Stills, and Nash
was also from Canada.
Throwing down two half chickens
on the grill.
Rick and Nat as a couple
are real characters.
The whole family travels
all over the place.
You just got back
from Thailand...
-I did.
-...where you row in a boat?
I paddle a dragon boat.
And you're on
the Canadian national team?
-I am.
-So you just row --
-Paddle.
-Paddle!
Paddle. In every division
we raced, we won.
We're always recruiting.
Maybe I get my whole
"Triple D" crew on.
What do you think?
Look like they're on
the dragon boat?
Look at them.
Here goes my team.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: And though she's known
here for champion chicken,
it's not just about the bird.
Beef ribs with salad up!
I always keep coming back here
for the ribs.
They're always quite tender
and flavorful.
Now we're gonna
make ribs.
We're gonna make
beef-rib rub.
Paprika, cumin,
oregano,
onion powder,
garlic powder,
chili powder, cayenne,
and salt and pepper.
Rub that onto
these beef ribs.
Put them in this pan
with some red wine.
You're gonna steam it...
-Yes.
-...slightly braise it.
How long are they gonna
be in the oven?
Three hours.
-What temp?
-325.
-Next up?
-Cherry-cola barbecue sauce.
-Alrighty then.
-Garlic oil.
Sauté ["So-tay"]
the chopped onions.
"So-tay"?
Is that not
an American word?
Onions are going to
get sauté.
Sweat those downs.
-Sweat-ay.
-I don't know what to say.
I don't know what to say
anymore.
Take the bad man
out of the kitchen.
Tomatoes, Worcester-
"Worchestishersour
sa-sauce"?
Yes. Ketchup,
roasted garlic.
Wow!
Beef rub, red wine vinegar,
brown sugar, salt.
-And?
-Liquid smoke.
The main ingredient?
Cherry cola.
You hit that with
the immersion blender.
You continue
to cook it down.
Look at those.
That's how many you get?
Three or four,
depending on size.
So we'll throw these
on the grill.
Give it a little baste.
Let them warm up.
There it is.
You don't see
beef ribs enough.
That's a very mature
beef rib.
They have, like,
a braised-beef flavor.
You definitely pick up the wine.
Good amount of the rub.
This is to cross between
a good old barbecue beef rib
and some
braised short ribs.
It's dynamite.
You want to talk about
tender and delicious,
these are good ribs.
Hi, guys.
I've got one order
of Texas-style beef ribs
for you, sir.
The best ribs in Ottawa,
in my opinion.
It's two simple things.
It's the moisture,
and it's the sauce.
Makes for a perfect meal.
One chicken finger
with fries up.
You feel like you're a family
when you come here.
And rock stars come here.
And rock stars.
It's good to keep coming back
when you have a big appetite.
FIERI: You give people
a real experience,
some real food,
for a real deal.
And I got to learn all about
dragon-boat racing.
Follow this girl.
They're gonna be doing
trading cards on her
any day now.
FIERI: Up next --
a happy little spot
in Burlington, Vermont...
All right.
...punching up the wings...
No traditional twang
to it.
...and making righteous ramen
with a smoky spin.
Real deal.
-Awesome. Thank you.
Real legit.
I'm so hung up on
this battling team.
What are you doing?
-Training for the rowing team.
-Paddling!
[ Laughs ]
[ Beep ]
Now, at "Triple D,"
we have been to just about
every state in the country.
But I got to be honest with you.
We haven't made it to Vermont
very many times,
and I don't know why.
But anyhow, we're driving
through town here
in Burlington, Vermont,
and we hear about a place.
It was a Mexican restaurant
for, like, 40 years,
and then it becomes
this barbecue place,
and it's got
a really funny name.
Wait a second.
That sounds just like
a "Triple D" joint to me.
This is Bluebird Barbecue.
MAN: Brisket's looking
really good.
The barbecue here
is absolutely fantastic.
Half chicken with coleslaw
and collard greens.
Every time I'm here,
there's something different,
and it's always
executed to perfection.
It's the best I've had
in New England.
FIERI: And it was one of the
first barbecue joints in Vermont
when owner Sue Bette
opened in 2012.
And now she's got Dan Miele
on board as the pitmaster.
What kind of barbecue
we doing?
We do a regional
American barbecue.
And then outside of that,
you do fusion, other stuff?
Yes.
Poutine with brisket.
Favorite thing
on the menu?
I think I'm eating it --
the wings.
Pitmaster wings
coming up right now.
The chicken is just
really juicy.
The white sauce that comes
with them is fantastic.
All right, let's get
into the wings.
MIELE: We're gonna make
our pitmaster rub --
brown sugar, kosher salt,
chili powder,
fresh-ground black pepper.
There you go.
Now, wait a second.
I want everybody
to look at this.
All gray.
Looks like gravel.
This fresh-ground
black pepper is key.
Garlic powder
and onion powder.
Okay.
So we got our wings
right here,
and then mix that
with cayenne-pepper hot sauce.
Let that marinate
for at least an hour,
and then right to the smoker --
250 for two hours.
And what are we
smoking with?
Oak, maple, and...
-Plywood.
-...hickory.
What do we serve
these with?
Alabama
white barbecue sauce.
It does have
a little bit of a kick
and an untraditional
twang to it.
-An untraditional what?
-Twang.
Twang! An untraditional
twang to it.
Water, rice wine vinegar,
sugar, ginger,
chili powder,
garlic cloves,
gojuchang.
[ Blender whirring ]
We're in the middle
of the race.
Mayonnaise --
we make it ourselves.
All right!
Let's get you
the overachiever metal.
Apple cider vinegar,
pitmaster rub
that we made before...
Got it.
...cayenne pepper, paprika,
ground mustard, cumin,
fresh-ground black pepper,
kosher salt, Worcester sauce.
"Washer-sister" sauce.
-And then our sauce.
-Yes!
So that's where the extra
twang is coming in.
Absolutely. This is gonna be
served on the side to dip.
I'll take a side of that
anytime.
Yes. Chicken wings come out,
and then we'll fry to order
and toss in a little bit more
pitmaster rub.
I can already tell you
we have an enormous problem
with the amount of
the twang sauce you gave me.
Oh, there's extras
on the table.
These wings aren't hot
at all.
I can just tell you this
right now.
The only thing that's wrong
with smoked fried wings --
too much smoke
and getting dried out.
And that's not
a problem here.
You have the right-size wing
to the right amount of smoke
to the right type of wood,
and then you've rendered them
just enough
that when you fry them,
a lot of the fat's cooked out,
so your fry is
quick and fast.
And the pitmaster rub
at the end
and then hitting
in that tangy sauce --
good kickoff, my friend.
Pitmaster wings
hitting the plate!
The smokiness and the flavor
really kind of hit you.
I would like an IV
of Alabama white sauce.
I would have it for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
Brisket plate with B&B pickles.
I love this place a lot.
FIERI: The big question is,
what's with the name?
Explain.
Bluebird of happiness.
Just wanted to be happy
every day I came to work.
Couldn't call it, like,
The Happy Hog?
MAN: The bluebird --
it's a rare bird.
You don't see it
all the time.
So here's this
rare bird in Vermont,
and here's some
really good barbecue.
Ribs here, sir.
So we're hanging out here
at the Bluebird Barbecue.
I know. The name is crazy.
But the food is legit.
We come back,
Chef's gonna make us...
MIELE: Pitmaster ramen.
The ramen's really good.
The barbecue flavors
with classic ramen flavors
just really comes together
nicely.
Get out of here.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back. Hanging out
in Burlington, Vermont.
We're at the
Bluebird Barbecue joint,
and I'll give you
some props, man.
You're pulling it off
in style, my friend.
Extra maple 'cue on that.
This is the most authentic
barbecue in Vermont. I love it.
FIERI: And they're taking
their classic 'cue
and running with it.
I got a pitmaster ramen,
add burnt ends!
Barbecue inside of ramen --
normal?
No. However, the flavors
really do pair well together.
It has that smoky flavor
that's delicious.
MIELE: We're gonna show you
how we make our burnt ends,
which is the topping
for our pitmaster ramen.
We going legit ramen?
-Very legit ramen.
-All right, let's see it.
Season this brisket up
with a salt-and-pepper blend.
This is gonna go
on the smoker how long?
15 hours.
We start it at 220,
and then we'll bump it up to 250
for the final two hours
of the smoking process.
Got it. Let's talk
about the beef broth.
So this is actually gonna be
a chicken broth. Yes.
-Really?
-A little different.
-All chicken bone?
-Just backs and necks.
Got it.
They have really
great collagen in there.
The collagen is what creates
that creaminess.
Then we have onions,
carrots, celery,
fresh thyme, bay leaves,
black peppercorns...
-Excellent.
-...and submerge with water.
-How long is this gonna run?
-12 hours.
And that's the stock that
we're holding for the dashi.
Absolutely.
Put in some ginger,
a little garlic...
Lemongrass.
...soy sauce,
bonito flakes, kombu.
Cilantro, green onions.
All right, how long
is this gonna go?
For an hour on high heat,
and then we're just gonna
drop it for 30 minutes
on a simmer and then strain it.
We also add
lime juice in ours
for a little bit
of brightness.
So here's our brisket.
Gorgeous.
We are going to take
the point of it off
and chop this up
into cubes.
Are those burners supposed
to be running back there?
No.
Super tender.
Not dry.
We cook till an internal
temperature of 203.
I cant have this.
I only cook to 202.
I can't have it!
Our pitmaster rub,
Texas-style barbecue sauce
right on there.
That you make in house,
also.
-Yes.
-Back to the smoker.
For one hour at 250.
So we're assembling our
pitmaster ramen right now.
Okay.
Drop our pre-blanched ramen
noodles in our dashi broth.
Where are the noodles from?
Sun Ramen Company
out of Hawaii.
-Yep.
-They're the best.
-Those are the ones.
-Our six-minute egg.
I can only have
a 4.3276519 egg.
-On high heat or low heat?
-That's on medium.
Noodles and broth
right into our bowl.
Pickled carrot
that we do in house.
Pickled jalapeño,
also done in house.
Shaved radishes.
Which we did
at the barber shop.
Some chopped scallions.
And then comes
our burnt ends.
Fresh cilantro,
toasted sesame oil.
That is how we do ramen.
Yeah, just what
I expected to see
when I walked into
the old Bluebird.
♪♪
Oh!
You guys are still here?
I was having a shovel fest.
The dashi broth is spot-on,
and it's actually
a little more aggressive
than maybe a typical dashi
because...
you're gonna drop in
these big pieces of burnt end,
which I was so worried
was just gonna turn into
a smoke pit.
But it doesn't.
Absolutely not.
Love the acid
of the pickling
and a really good noodle.
-Yeah.
-Legit, bro.
Noodles going in.
The meat is so tender and juicy.
It's got that umami,
the whole sweet and sour
and deliciousness.
I have a half smoked chicken
with slaw and collards!
If you've got barbecue
in your name,
it better be good barbecue,
and this is the best barbecue
I've ever had.
If we don't come every
other week, my kids are like,
"When are we going
to Bluebird again?
I like how you play
this little game, like,
"Hey, we're just
a barbecue pit.
Come in. Let us get
our talons on you."
Real deal.
-Awesome. Thank you.
Real legit.
I'll get 10 ramens to go.
FIERI: Coming up -- Texas flavor
in Richmond, Virginia...
This might be the biggest
collective of monster 'cues
I've seen in my life.
...and one of the most
massive mountains of meat.
If you're gonna go
to all that effort,
it better be delicious,
and it really is.
♪♪
So I'm here in Richmond,
Virginia, to check out a joint
where a husband-and-wife team,
well, they're paying respects
to his Texas roots
and one of my favorite bands,
ZZ Top.
You see, folks,
I'm just a sharp-dressed man,
and I'm not wearing
cheap sunglasses.
But you got me
under pressure.
You see, I have a responsibility
to bring you
some of the best barbecue
you've ever seen on "Triple D,"
and after this spot,
you'll say, "I thank you."
This is ZZQ.
All right, let's check
on these ribs.
I love Texas barbecue,
and this is
the best place for it.
How'd you find this place?
A buddy of mine sent me
a picture of his plate,
and we've been coming
ever since.
Alex and Chris are exceptionally
good at what they do.
FIERI: Which hasn't always
been just 'cue.
So you're both architects.
Is that how you met?
No.
Oh, this should be good.
I was playing roller derby.
I went to my first
roller-derby bout
and saw her on the track,
and that was that.
FIERI: Then when Alex Graf
and Chris Fultz
skated off as a team, they
discovered their new passion.
We're doing
Texas barbecue?
Yeah, yeah.
Starts with brisket,
pulled-pork shoulder,
pork spare ribs.
We do our own sausages
in house.
The habanero-Fontina sausage
is my favorite.
It has spicy habaneros
balanced by the Fontina cheese.
You cut it open,
and you can see the cheese melt
right out of them.
Make your own sausage.
That's what we're
gonna make right now?
-Yes, sir.
-Let's see it.
Minced garlic,
crushed red pepper...
-Hi, antacid.
-...a little toasted coriander,
cayenne for just
a little more heat.
That's just a touch?
Granulated onion,
coarse ground black pepper.
Got it.
So now we're gonna
season the meat --
beef, pork, and fat back.
Nice, lean,
delicate sausage.
Yeah.
Now we're gonna go
into the grinder.
Wisconsin Fontina,
habanero peppers.
I'm a big fan
of the spice,
but what is the heat level?
It's up there.
It's the hottest sausage
by far that we make.
Final ingredient --
cilantro.
After I get this mixed up,
put a little...
a little ice water.
All right,
ready to stuff some sausage.
Here we go. We're gonna do
a cool smoke on them
for about an hour and a half,
around 120, 150 degrees.
Okay, and then we'll make
the pickles.
Yep.
We've got some cucumbers.
We're gonna run
some Fresno through.
Okay. Let's make
the pickling brine.
A boatload of
apple cider vinegar,
kosher salt, sugar,
celery seed, dill seed.
Aren't you the gangster?
Mustard seed,
fresh red pepper,
fresh garlic, onions.
We're gonna put together
a little sachet of dill,
black peppercorns,
some bay leaves.
All right, so let that
come to a boil.
Pour it over the top
of the cucumbers.
Oh, and here's the kicker.
They're all free.
We don't charge for them.
It's complimentary.
I love
your business model.
-All right. Finished product.
-I'll have all of them.
Habanero Fontina,
pickled red onions,
ceviche onions,
pickles we just made,
jalapeños,
pickled carrots.
That's all she wrote.
That's good heat.
Not overly hot.
Saltiness of the cheese.
You got texture.
You got snap,
and the great thing is
is you come in here
for some of these...
Free pickled items.
Yeah.
...the free pickled items.
They cleanse the palate.
If you're gonna go
to all that effort,
it better be delicious,
and it really is.
-Awesome.
-Architect, huh?
-Mm-hmm.
-Yeah, right.
Yeah.
The habanero-Fontina sausage
has a nice, crisp crunch.
Just the right amount of heat
and great flavor,
goes wonderful with the pickles.
Couple ribs.
Enjoy.
When did the love of barbecue
come about?
I'm a transplanted Texan
living in Virginia.
I've met pit masters.
I've competed in barbecue.
This might be the biggest
collective of monster 'cues
I've seen in my life.
We have three here and then
one out in the backyard.
It's like I'm right
in central Texas.
Tres Hombres.
MAN: Tres Hombres has
a Fontina-habanero sausage
as well as pulled pork,
and it has brisket.
And it is a big one.
-We're gonna make the...
-Tres Hombres sandwich.
We're gonna build our dry rub
for our pulled pork.
Let's see it.
Course ground black pepper,
kosher salt, a little paprika,
chili powder, brown sugar,
granulated garlic,
and granulated onion.
We're gonna take
our Boston butt,
apply a yellow-mustard-
and-pickle brine, slather.
Okay.
Rub the butt pretty heavily
with our dry rub.
They'll smoke
for about 12 hours.
Okay, on to the brisket.
And again, we're gonna start
with black pepper,
kosher salt, paprika,
little cayenne...
For my homies.
...granulated garlic,
granulated onion,
cumin, Mexican oregano.
Oh, that's what
I was gonna say.
The mustard-and-pickle-brine
slather.
Dry rub.
And then this is gonna go
for how long?
About 16 to 18 hours.
We're gonna make our signature
house thick sauce.
What are we missing?
Um, a ballet slipper
and an engine block.
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna toast
three types of chilies,
and we're gonna be
caramelizing some onions.
So while that's going,
we're gonna start the tea.
Oil.
Good. Let's get every pot,
every ingredient.
Garlic, water,
toasted peppers.
-Let them steep.
-20 minutes.
Take all this and pour it
into a blender.
Puree it.
Got it.
We're gonna start
the next step
with the
caramelized onions.
Okay.
I add molasses to that.
Cook that down.
We're gonna add
the tea that we made.
Ketchup.
-Apple cider vinegar.
-Brown sugar.
Cumin, chili flake,
whole-grain mustard,
kitchen sink,
eye of newt, wing of bat.
Pickling brine, soy,
lemon juice.
-Cayenne.
-Salt.
Cook it for an hour
to an hour and a half.
We're done. We're gonna put
the Tres Hombres together.
Habanero Fontina,
pulled pork,
thick sauce,
beef brisket,
a little more thick sauce,
pickled red onions.
Okay.
Oh, how cute.
We'll put
the little hat on it.
Just for you.
I'm not gonna be
a sharp-dressed man after this.
♪♪
This is a monster.
Delicious brisket.
Love the sausage.
Pulled pork's
nice and tender.
It's legit.
It's real-deal.
It's great flavor.
Well done, Chef.
Thank you.
Tres Hombres.
You have to really press down
to fit in your mouth.
The brisket is very tender.
It's really delicious.
Pulled-pork shoulder platter.
The food is made with love.
You can taste it.
Everybody here in Richmond
kind of lucked out.
They got a couple who love
barbecue, love adventure,
from roller derby
to the crazy, action-packed life
of architecture.
To quote the old ZZ Top,
"I want to thank you."
FULTZ: Thank you.
Was that a road trip or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for
your next time on "Triple D."
You come here from the
United States with one chicken.
You get a chicken and a half
in Canada.
It's chicken conversion.
I love this country.
Go Ottawa.