Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
This trip...
Huh-huh-huh-huh!
...we're lighting up the
Latin...
Ohh!
...all over the map.
Are we in Flavortown
right now?
I am at customs.
There's Salvadoran specialties
in Logan, Utah...
Whoo!
And a "Whoo!"
...Mexican tacos
in Burlington, Vermont...
Dude. Where did you
learn to cook?
...and a funky food truck
in Denver...
It's a game changer.
...kicking Puerto Rican
in overdrive.
You know you're going
to find this truck?
Parked at my house
in Northern California.
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here, right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
"So remember back in the day" --
I love when people
start stories like that,
like, "Back in the day."
Well, back in the day when
we first started "Triple D,"
you'd have to really go
to Southern California
to get a great Mexican taco
or go all the way down to Texas
to get brisket
or over to New England
to get great chowder.
Well, times have changed,
of course,
but you know one food
we don't see enough of
all over the country --
Puerto Rican food.
Oh, you got to go down
to South Miami,
you got to get yourself
down to Puerto Rico,
unless you happen
to be in Denver
because this food truck
is doing the real deal.
This is Areyto.
Rice, beans,
and an order of the tostones.
We don't go to any other
food truck besides Areyto's.
It's like having a piece of
the island in four wheels.
Bleach his hair,
have him cover Monday.
[ Laughter ]
Pork bowl with amarillos.
It tastes just like my
grandmother or my mother
would make it.
FIERI:
That's because Erik Elias
and Yari Ortiz
are cooking up
the kind of grub
her grandmother and mom
would make in Puerto Rico.
What do people say to you
about the first time
they have Puerto Rican food?
They love it. I mean,
Puerto Rican food
has poignant flavors.
-Where are you from?
-El Salvador.
Now did you know much about
Puerto Rican food before this?
No, to be honest with you.
She introduce me to mofongo
and all that stuff.
Here's your chicken mofongo,
enjoy.
The mofongo is a plantain
they fry and mash it.
And then you have the chicken
marinated in this amazing sauce.
And so you have your sweet,
you have your savory.
It's a warm hug.
Big guy
in a little trailer.
-[ Laughs ]
-What are we making first?
Sofrito.
This is the basis of our food.
We're going to be using this
on our chicken
that goes into the mofongo.
Okay.
Start with the cilantro.
Yellow onions.
I'll start putting
some water in here
so we can start blending this.
[ Whirring ]
Things are getting a little
out of control!
-Green peppers.
-Yep.
Green onions,
top it up with the garlic.
That was the most violent --
You had your elbow
in there and your shoe.
So the next step is we're
going to make the chicken.
Put it into our pressure
cooker, the sofrito.
A little chicken base.
Some salt, tomato puree.
Got it.
Then we put a little water.
So this is going to cook
for an hour.
This will just make this chicken
all delicious and shreddable?
Yes, very tender, very moist.
This means moist
in Puerto Rican
in case anybody
didn't know.
I'm learning with you now.
Very moist.
Okay, so, when the chicken
comes out, we shred it.
Yeah. And then we actually
put peppers and onions
for another five minutes
so that they can get soft.
And then we --
Shredded. Soft.
And then it's
all good to go.
And what's the base
of the mofongo?
It's actually plantains.
The plantains.
Once you cut them...
Let them fry until
they're...
Cut them into smaller pieces,
and then stir them in the pilon.
What are we going
to add to that?
Olive oil, garlic, salt.
And then we're going to
mix it all together.
And then once we have the mold
ready, we put the meat inside.
Au jus right in there.
Ohh!
It's a chicken bowl
of fun.
♪♪
It's dynamite.
It's better than dynamite.
It's as legit as any mofongo
I've ever had.
I mean, even though it's got
great moisture in itself,
just a little kiss of that
broth you spooned on,
is a game changer.
Oh. This is so good.
You know where you're
going to find this truck?
Parked at my house
in northern California.
Here's your chicken mofongo,
enjoy.
The chicken's fantastic.
She has it seasoned really nice.
I could eat the plantains
by themselves.
Delicious. I invite everybody
to come and try it.
How do people find you around
the greater Denver area?
We post our schedule on Facebook
and we also have a website.
Anything else on the menu
I should try?
Two alcapurrias are ready.
The alcapurria is a classic
fritter from Puerto Rico.
It's crunchy on the outside
with a little bit of meat in it.
It's all delicious.
What is next on the game?
The alcapurrias.
We're going to start
with the meat, oil and onions.
A little of the sofrito.
Ground beef.
Yep. The salt, adobo,
tomato sauce,
and now olives at the end.
Next up.
Now we're going to make
the masa for alcapurrias.
The alcapurria masa.
Yes.
You don't get to say
that very often.
What's your name?
Alcapurria.
Alcapurria Masa.
I'm a secret agent
of Flavortown.
Alcapurria Masa.
This is the taro root,
cut it into smaller chunks.
While you're grating that,
I can start cutting
the green bananas.
It's all right here, right now
with Alcapurria Masa.
[ Laughs ]
Mix these together.
A little annatto oil.
Yeah. The Adobo.
And a touch of the salt.
Yep. Place some Masa.
Oh, you need
lots o' Masa.
On wax paper.
Hey, lots o' Masa.
We start filling it.
Pinch it together,
push it down a little bit.
And then that goes directly
in the fryer
without the paper, though?
Yep. And that's
our alcapurria fritter.
Excuse me, I'm not
from Puerto Rico,
but if I can say something,
that looks like the work
of Alcapurria --
Alcapurria Masa.
♪♪
It's light, it's tender,
it's fluffy, not heavy.
The piccadillo
inside of it, dynamite.
The little bit of batter
that's on the outside of it,
it's got a great chew to it,
and then goes super soft.
Fantastic.
Alcapurrias ready.
Flavor is really nice
and the texture
is really, really good.
It's very tedious to make them,
but they do a great job.
Steak jibarito
ready to go.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Proud of you guys.
You're doing it the right way.
You're doing it with a lot
of love, a lot of enthusiasm.
You're awesome.
Thank you so much.
Well done.
I appreciate that.
And this is Alcapurria Masa,
saying good night.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you so much.
Whoosh!
Did we get a...
No, we're still
standing here?
Okay, that was weird.
FIERI:
Up next in Logan, Utah...
Behind the scenes,
ladies and gentlemen.
...a Salvadorian spot
putting out prima pupusas...
That is the perfect
money bite right there.
...and making sopes
that are ahead of their time.
Sopes are one of my favorite
things, but the cabeza.
Cabeza is the head.
I just want to call him.
Maybe he'll come save me.
-Who?
-Alcapurria.
-Alcapurria...Masa.
[ Laughs ]
I'm here in Logan, Utah
with those beautiful
snowcapped mountains
in the background.
Can't beat it.
Now this is home
to Utah State University.
So with all those
college students,
what kind of food
do you think you find here?
Well, you find
some great burgers, definitely.
Pizza. Probably
some great steak houses.
But when I hear
that there's a joint
where the dude grew up
in Guatemala,
right on the border
of El Salvador,
and he's serving up
some real deal pupusas,
I've got to check it out.
This is El Salvador Los Primos.
♪♪
How the pupusas are coming?
This place is amazing.
It's authentic.
One plate of
tacos Michoacánas.
Come back three,
four times a week.
I'm from El Salvador
and it feels like
I'm back home
when I come here.
FIERI: That's because
Luis Ramos, his wife, Carla,
and her mother, Esperanza Sosa,
brought the flavors of back home
with them to the States.
15 years ago,
I moved to New York
and then I start getting passion
for working in a restaurant.
Okay.
I came in Utah because I meet
my wife in Guatemala,
but she had brother here.
I'm going to have to
come to you there
because, well, you know...
Huh-huh-huh-ha!
And I marry her.
Hang on a second.
Did anybody else catch
the huh-huh translation?
[ Laughter ]
I have to open
my own business
because I have
to do this for myself.
Is it a taqueria, is it --
No, it's pupuseria.
So pupusas are the key?
Yes.
Hey guys, I got your pork
and cheese pupusas.
A pupusa is kind of a thick
fried tortilla
filled with refried beans,
plus some other fillings.
It just makes
your mouth water.
So we making our chicharrónes
for the pupusas.
Huh-huh-huh-huh!
Heat the lard, and now we
add in the pork butt.
Just be careful
because this is very hot.
I'm right over here.
A little bit of salt,
a little garlic.
So this fries up
till it's crispy.
About an hour and a half.
Then we're going
to grind it?
Yes.
And this is going to make
the filling for the pupusa?
-Exactly.
-Okay.
The chicharrónes.
Peppers, onions, tomatoes.
Garlic, salt,
and chicken bouillon.
All right, Chef. Next up?
Refried beans. So I have
these beans soak in water
from last night.
Put in the boiling water.
We got the onions now.
Whole garlic,
little bit salt.
Once the beans get
cooked through,
grind them,
and then go to refry them.
Yes, we put in the oil,
onions, garlic,
get that little brown,
nice color.
After that, we putting
in the blender.
Grind that up. Everybody back
in the pot to make the refry?
We add in the oil, the beans,
and the onions blend.
Got it.
Now we make the pupusa dough.
So I have the Maseca flour.
Just putting
some water in there.
You know, this is kind of
like a workout.
You don't have to go
to the gym anymore.
Come down for
the comedy show.
All right, so I need her
to check that.
So you have to bring
in your mother-in-law,
who's the real boss.
Well, you know what?
I normally don't make this here.
Behind the scenes,
ladies and gentlemen.
Look, she's just [whistles]
And she's doing it
with one hand.
The two of us would have
been here all week.
Gracias.
Okay, so now we mix
in the fillings.
Got the chicharrón,
got the refried beans,
little bit cheese.
Okay. Should I bring in
the jefe?
We both make it so you
see which one is better.
We'll see.
Making little hole in here,
put in a little bit
this stuffing here
in the middle and...
Ah! She's here.
Let me see.
Look at the boss here.
Hold him out like that.
Okay, so this is round,
and this is
enh-oh-enh-oh-enh-oh!
She's the primo.
So we put these on,
and we make the slaw.
So I got the vinegar in there,
I got the water in here.
-Do we turn these?
-Oh, yeah.
You looking for a job?
I'm trying right now to
keep up with the one I got.
Oregano,
and a little bit of salt.
Blend this up.
Strain, cabbage,
some onions,
carrots,
add in the liquid.
-You ready to plate it up?
-Yep.
All right, good.
Putting the sauce in here.
There we go.
♪♪
Wow. I've had some pupusas,
but not with this much flavor.
That's dynamite. This is like
a tamale meets a tortilla.
Nice and creamy
in the middle,
a little texture on the outside,
perfectly seasoned.
And then when you add
in the slaw with this salsa,
and you get that
acidic balance,
I mean that is the perfect
money bite right there.
In Flavortown,
we have a word for this...
Huh-huh-huh!
[ Laughs ]
Come on down
and try some of the...
Huh-huh-huh!
Pupusas, bean
and chicharrónes is ready.
You can taste the chicharrónes.
I like to get one
that's a little bit crunchy.
Just the right amount
of filling.
I've got six kids.
We buy probably 30 or 40 pupusas
because we eat a lot.
And then we get extra
because in the morning,
the next morning
for breakfast...
You got to have a pupusa
in the morning.
...you got to have pupusas
Nice and fresh and ohhh.
Flautas for table two
is ready.
There's nothing like this
in town. Everything's good.
Here's the deal. I want to
eat this entire thing,
but I can't because you
can already see my eyes
going into the food coma.
What else are we going to have?
Sopes, and we cooking
the cabeza.
-What?
-Cabeza.
-Like the cow.
Cabeza is the head.
Sope la cabeza.
It was actually really good.
I really can't stop
eating them.
Winner, winner,
head cheese dinner.
Well, doesn't that sound fun?
We'll see in a little bit.
♪♪
Welcome back. "Triple D"
hanging out here
in Logan, Utah,
at El Salvador Los Primos
with Chef Luis,
flavor over the top,
and I'm back for you
because you know what he said
he's going to make me?
Cabeza sopes.
Sopes are one
of my favorite things,
but the cabeza?
-You have to say that.
-Cabeza is the head.
Putting some cabeza
on the sope.
Cabeza is not comfort food
for just everybody. Right?
It's a mixture of tongue
and cheek, and it's very unique.
Waste not, want not. You've
got to use the entire animal.
People really do love
the cabeza.
We always run out.
Well, if we run out,
please don't let me
be the greedy one
that takes one.
We using the cheeks,
lips, and tongue.
Now we add in the water,
whole garlic,
onions, bay leaf.
A lot of bay leaf.
And salt. This is taking
like four to five hours.
Then when it comes out,
we're going to...?
Take all the skin out.
Okay. Then we're
going to chop it up.
-Yep.
-So what are we making?
We making
the guajillo sauce.
So these are
guajillo chiles
that have been steeped
in hot water.
And a little bit water.
Cumin, garlic,
a little bit of salt,
bay leaf,
cloves, whole pepper,
black pepper.
-Going to strain it?
-Yeah.
What we have to do
is continue to move it
because all the solids stick
to the bottom of the strainer.
This will make it
so it's really nice and silky.
We bring the cabeza.
Welcome to chunk a cow.
Now we go to the pan, little bit
of oil, the guajillo sauce.
Bringing the band
back together.
Okay, how long are we going
to let this cook?
5 to 10 minutes.
So now we go make the tortilla
for the sope.
-Okay.
-My tortilla press in here,
you make a kind of
like little ball in there.
Okay.
All right.
Have to cook it for like
about three to five minutes.
So just going to put a little
crust on the outside.
So I've got my sope
ready here.
We go on the border.
The sope becomes kind of
like a thick taco cup.
Drop in the fryer, 350, we bring
it back and then we load it up.
Yep. Little crema,
sour cream, the cabeza.
Ooh, yeah.
Lettuce, tomato,
onions on it,
an avocado,
and little more crema.
Oh, you go, dawg.
Little bit cotija cheese.
Well, I'm scared
I'm going to burn my tongue
with the tongue.
Don't get lippy with me now.
It's delicious.
Super tender.
The sope's nice and crunchy.
When you see how many people
in this community
are coming here just for this,
it is dynamite.
Everything that it takes
to get to this sope
is a lot of work,
and the flavors are outstanding.
You know what we say
about that, right?
-Huh-huh-huh-huh.
[ Laughter ]
Sope de cabeza.
This is fantastic.
Super tender.
The crispiness of the sope,
so money.
Its flavor profile was much
deeper than just
a regular sope
that I'm used to.
How close is that
to traditional?
This is the real deal.
I grew up with this food.
It's such a comfort
to come and have it.
So I will give you the true
El Salvador Los Primos
huh-huh-huh-huh.
Chef Luis, nice job.
Whoo!
And a "Whoo!"
Watch out for this cat.
FIERI: Coming up,
south of the border
up in Burlington, Vermont...
Oh, this I got to try.
...at a joint on fire...
[ Voice breaking ]
No, it's not hot at all.
...with their real deal tacos.
One of the closest I've been
to having authentic al pastor
outside of Mexico.
♪♪
You know, I remember talking
to friends from the East coast
about Mexican food,
and they're all kind of like,
"Man, I don't
like Mexican food."
And it was usually because they
were having
fast-food Mexican food.
And then it meant that you'd
have to go down to California
or the Southwest
to get real authentic.
-Well, times are changing.
-Order up.
It is opening up
all over the country.
I'm here in Burlington, Vermont.
I hear this dude's rocking it.
This is Taco Gordo.
Got two brisket here.
MAN: Taco Gordo is the best
Mexican food
this close to
the Canadian border.
Tinga brisket.
Beans and rice.
I'm from California, and this is
the first place in Vermont
that I felt encapsulated
what a true taco is.
Real deal
Southwestern, Mexican.
I didn't know how much I needed
Charlie's tacos.
FIERI: That craving took hold
when Charlie Sizemore
first rolled out
his taco cart in 2014.
Then blew it up
to a brick and mortar
bringing a West coast flavor
all the way to New England.
Where do you get license
to taco?
I had family living
in California and Arizona,
so have a really
close relationship.
We've had tacos there
before.
Yes.
Two al pastor tacos for you.
I love the al pastor.
The way they roast it
on the spit, the pineapple.
You can't get a better taco.
It's just like
a religious experience.
Today we're going to do
the al pastor.
We're making our house
adobo.
We start with our dried spices
and chilies.
We toast these off.
The guajillas, the pasillas,
and the chipotles?
Yes.
I like it.
What else are we doing?
Peppercorns, cloves, cumin.
Got it. Some cinnamon.
This, I'm impressed with it.
The annatto seed.
Yes.
Dude, where'd
you learn to cook?
A misspent youth.
He was in a band called
Misspent Youth.
The beautiful thing
about that annatto seed,
really gives that beautiful
red hue in Latin food.
These go on to soak.
Let me set some background
steeping music.
[ Spice grinder whirring ]
-You're good at that.
-Well, it's misspent youth.
We're playing a show
later on.
Yes, I have the album.
Can you sign my shirt?
Chiles into the blender
here.
Apple cider vinegar,
raw blackened garlic.
Our spice mix.
Oregano, sugar, salt.
A little more liquid.
We're going to use
boneless pork butt?
Yes. We get it cold,
slice it thin.
How long will you
let this pork marinate?
At least a day.
Got it.
Start stacking.
The al pastor looks fantastic.
Pineapple on top?
Pineapple on top.
Super important.
Next up?
Is our salsa roja.
Okay.
Guajillas,
a couple of chipotles,
roasted tomatoes,
toasted garlic,
ground cumin, oregano, sugar,
salt, apple cider vinegar.
Great.
Little bit
of steeping liquid.
Delicious. Love the toasting
of the garlic.
Little kiss of the sugar.
Well done.
Little bit of lard, tortillas.
While these are cooking,
I'm going to slice you
a little bit of this al pastor.
Love the pineapple on top.
Little onion and cilantro.
This is our salsa roja here.
♪♪
This is outstanding.
This is also probably
one of the closest I've been
to having authentic al pastor
outside of Mexico.
♪♪
Mmm.
The tortilla is great.
The al pastor is tender.
It's got a ton of flavor.
There was a good amount
of char on this.
The marinade comes through.
The little piece of pineapple
on top is key.
Are we in Flavortown
right now?
I am at customs.
I am crossing the border.
That is a dynamite taco.
Welcome to Flavortown.
Two al pastor
going to the bar.
It's fantastic.
Smoky, rich, a lot of sweetness.
Every time I look at it,
my mouth waters.
MAN: I love the different
hot sauces that he has.
He definitely isn't afraid
to use some that
are a little hotter than
the other places around here.
The only problem you got
is you played your hit single
right off the bat.
Well, you haven't had
the beans.
You shouldn't sleep
on the beans.
And what does don't sleep
on the beans mean?
Everybody looks past
the beans,
they're looking
at the al pastor.
I always get the grandma's beans
tacos, not boring beans.
I would eat
this this every day.
And where was
this recipe from?
It's an old family recipe.
Oh, this I got to try.
Oil in the pan, onion,
carrot, serranos,
garlic, little bit of cumin.
That's a lot of bit
of cumin.
Next in are the dried
pinto beans soaked overnight.
Got it.
Cover that with water and cook
those until they burst.
We finish it with cumin
and salt.
The oranges also go in
at the end.
Finishes
for about 30 minutes.
Our favorite is to eat them with
the carrot habanero hot sauce.
Oh, this I got to see.
It's a Belizian preparation.
Oil hot in a pan, onions,
carrots, garlic.
Caramelize them a bit.
And then we're adding
some water just to cover.
Now we're just blending
these fresh habaneros.
This will be a nice mild salsa.
A little bit of lime juice.
Some vinegar, salt.
You ready?
I'll be back here.
Oh, I want to try this.
Hot, hot, hot, hot.
[ Voice breaking ]
No, it's not hot at all.
Oh, free water.
Real deal salsa.
Not just blow your mouth
out hot salsa.
Flavorful.
Little sweet. Delicious.
How many would you like?
Dos, por favor.
Absolutely.
I think in the history
of "Triple D,"
we've never had
a bean taco.
If you're going to make
a bean taco,
they better be some
righteous beans.
They better be.
Our first album,
Righteous Beans.
♪♪
And what do you call
the beans on the menu?
The Bean.
That is pretty just
U2 or Bowie.
You think you got
that kind of pull here?
I think so.
Onion. Cilantro.
I'm going to put the paint
stripper on myself?
Yeah, yeah.
The key is the beans.
Tender, but firm,
and they give you a texture.
Very flavorful.
The cumin and the citrus
at the end,
they just shine.
But when you dress it up
with a little bit
of the habanero carrot,
give it a little
kiss of some lime,
and you've got that fresh
cilantro and onion on there...
delicious.
-Bean tacos for you.
-It's nice and creamy.
Luxurious
and also substantial.
I love the habanero sauce.
It's not too overwhelming.
You can still taste the food,
and it brightens
the dish up as well.
Two tinga, two al pastor.
It's one of my favorite spots
to come to.
There's nothing else in town
that comes close.
FIERI: This is better Mexican
food than I've had in places
25 miles from Mexico.
Dude, you kill it.
Thank you.
Well done.
That's it for this week,
but don't you worry,
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I knight you, Sir Napkin.
[ Laughter ]
Don't sleep on the beans.