You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D'?
How they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
That's good eats
right there, man.
In Kansas City...
I am so gonna regret
saying this.
...a pizza slinging,
meat smoking pal...
That is almost touching.
That's going coast to coast.
...with a personality
the size of his pies.
Very weird.
A corner joint in
Cambridge, Massachusetts...
The crunch
and the mess.
...schooling me on their
cultural classics....
This is Greek 101
right here.
...and it's all
music to my ears.
♪ Lamb-a, lamb-a, lamb-y,
lamb-y, lamb-y ♪
Plus, a Mexican spot in Maryland
so off the hook...
The salsa gives you that little
bit of, my nose is running.
...I had to phone a friend.
It's a story you hear
every day, Joe.
[ Laughs ]
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
You know, on "Triple D," there's
a few things you can count on.
You always count
on the Camaro is here.
You can count on the fact
that I got some shades,
and you can probably
count on the fact
that I'm gonna say
something is off the hook.
Off the hook.
And when I come to Kansas City,
you can expect
I'll be looking for
Stretch at Grinders.
Stretch Phillys,
all the way, Cheez Whiz.
MAN: Grinders is absolutely
a destination for downtown.
I mean, if you want authentic,
great Kansas City food
in a unique environment,
this is the place to be.
Yoo-hoo!
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN: Once everyone realized
there was something so cool
that they could see
in this part of town,
people just started
to flock to it.
It's exploded.
Chili Bomb!
GUY: All because of this dude,
the one and only Stretch.
MAN:
Oh, you put two people like Guy
and Stretch in the same room,
you have no idea
what's gonna happen.
Oh, yeah!
A little cut.
Did you, because you knew
I was coming today,
fashion your hair
in my style?
Or am I following
your lead?
I'm the guy that colors
outside the lines.
I think I'm gonna
dye it red
and do
a Bozo the Clown thing.
I like the way
you're rolling.
How many years ago
was it that we did "Triple D"?
'07.
We haven't cleaned
since you've been here,
just to make sure
it's authentic.
[ Whispering ]
You're weird!
[ Laughs ]
[ Normal voice ]
Very weird.
He's got his own very unique
style and pretty unique food.
It's very much
Stretch.
I say we make our famous
Bengal Tiger.
A little pesto
goes down.
We sprinkle on
our Tandoori chicken.
Curry.
Little curry
on there.
Crab meat.
Hearts of palm.
Hearts of palm?
I mean, eye of newt,
wing of bat...
I mean, who's using
those anymore?
And we sprinkle a little
of our cheese on top,
and that's about it
right there.
That is gorgeous!
Bengal Tiger.
Rawr!
Delicious.
You get, like,
these gems,
little hearts of palm,
little bit of the chicken.
It really works.
WOMAN: You're not gonna find
this pizza anywhere else.
It's probably the best
in Kansas City.
There's
the Crossroads.
♪♪
Great.
The Goldberg.
It's got
a little salmon,
we put some cream cheese
on there, some capers.
That's weird.
Tasty, but weird.
I like it
that way.
Give me the update
that I'm probably aware of,
but everybody at home
wants to know.
The chaotic world.
Alright, good.
Thank you very much.
Good talk.
Nice time.
See you later.
Thanks for
tuning in.
But quickly, not in
Stretch language,
give it to me
in regular language.
We expanded west,
right next door.
We opened in Lenexa, Kansas,
we have Grinders Stonewall,
then we opened up in
Leavenworth, Kansas,
where our brewery is,
called Grinders High Noon,
and we now have
our food truck.
I couldn't tell that was
your food truck when I drove by.
There just wasn't enough
graphics and color on it.
[ Car horn honks ]
Anything new on the menu
that I need to try?
Yeah, you've got to try
our Mixon sandwich.
It's a smoked
brisket sandwich.
Start with a really
nice brisket,
put a nice
rub over that,
then we're gonna
make our injection.
It's a little
Grinders rub.
Water, soy sauce,
beef base.
We want
a lot more flavor
and give it a little
more enhancement.
Sits overnight,
eight hours minimum,
then it hits our smoke
for about 12 hours.
Slice about
an eighth-inch thick.
Just let that warm up
a little on the grill.
Then, we add
our Swiss cheese --
two slices.
House-made
onion straws.
And let's add our Grinders
barbecue sauce
with our kettle chips.
And you make
your own chips.
Yeah.
Sliced, soak them
in water,
add some vinegar in there,
some salt.
Sits for
about 24 hours,
then it's dropped
in the fryer.
Look at that.
I'll give it to you.
That is some
smoke ring, dude.
I mean, that is almost touching.
That's going coast to coast.
♪♪
That's legit.
What are you rubbing it with?
So --
I'm sorry, let me open up
this shameless plug.
What are you
smoking it with?
So that's smoked with
a hickory wood, a pecan,
and we put Grinders
signature rub on there,
which is
a trade secret.
[ Chuckles ]
That's good.
WOMAN: Alright,
I have a Mixon.
I come here
just for this.
It's a mouthful.
The cheese was perfectly melted.
What you get is
a nice smoky taste.
I can't get
enough of it.
WOMAN: The barbecue sauce
was really sweet.
It's goodness
in the mouth.
Sauce is good.
You make the sauce, also?
Yep. Started making
sauce here.
It's also available
at many locations --
Oh, God.
I'm out of here.
If you're not
even shopping,
you can buy the Grinders
barbecue sauce
at many locations
around the country.
♪♪
GUY:
But coming up...
[ Whispering ]
It's off the menu.
Oh, good.
...Stretch is trying to keep
some things in the fold.
[ Normal voice ]
Get ready to start making
a bunch of those, brother.
The secret's out.
Yeah.
...and they might just be
his craziest masterpieces yet.
Outside the box.
You need to be
put inside a box,
is what you need
to be put in.
[ Laughs ]
Bengal Tiger!
GUY:
It's the old "Triple D" motto.
"If it's funky,
we'll find it."
And back in 2007,
[Chuckles]
I found it in Kansas City.
An old auto parts store
turned restaurant,
run by a transplanted
East Coaster sculptor,
where the place and the food
are both off the hook.
Welcome to Grinders.
And my brother Stretch
is still slinging slices
and churning out cheesesteaks.
Philly's up!
We had the cheesesteak when we
were here 12 years ago, right?
We did.
It's the meat. It's the bread.
It's the love.
The secret is definitely
seasoning the grill beforehand.
Nice lean
roast beef we use.
Chop it up.
The other secret
is slicing the bun.
You don't want to go
all the way through.
Peppers first, then put
a little onions on there
and mix it in there.
Pour cheese
right across the top.
That's a Philly cheesesteak
in Kansas City.
Cheers.
Bon appetit.
That's good eats
right there, man.
It's
a Stretch Philly.
It's half pastrami that we do
in house, and half ribeye.
Wait, wait, wait, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
You make
a pastrami ribeye cheesesteak?
Yes, sir.
And it's
on the menu?
[ Whispering ]
It's off the menu.
Oh, good.
It's on
our secret menu.
I'll have
one of those.
[ Normal voice ]
Bring it on.
STRETCH:
So, we've got our corned beef,
trimmed it all down.
Now what we're gonna do
is mix up our blend.
Garlic powder, onion powder,
paprika, brown sugar,
dry mustard, coriander,
black pepper.
And we rub that baby down
and smoke it in the smoker
for about eight hours.
Shave it really thin
on the slicer.
Amoroso roll all the way
from Philadelphia.
Put some of our wonderful
ribeye down.
Pastrami, green peppers, onions,
mushrooms, chicken stock.
Ribeye has a real
nice beefy texture.
Adding that pastrami
gives it a little more fat,
which is always good.
Provolone,
three slices.
[ Whispering ] The Stretch
Philly, half pastrami.
[ Whispering ]
Nobody'll know.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
[ Normal voice ]
Okay.
I am so gonna regret
saying this,
but I will
be honest with you.
The pastrami addition
to that is rock star.
You're using
really good ribeye.
There's a little bit
of that texture
coming through
from the pastrami,
a little bit
of that pepper.
Dude,
it's dynamite.
Get ready to start making
a bunch of those, brother.
The secret's out.
Cool.
Two Stretch Phillys
coming up.
Stacked full of meat,
lot of cheese, super gooey.
You can really get
a lot of flavor out of it.
WOMAN:
Best Philly in town.
It's got all
the vegetables in it.
Cheese, meat.
Ah! You can't go wrong with it.
Thanks for eating our pie.
That's Grinders.
417 East 18th Street,
Kansas City, Missouri.
Grinders! www.com.
[ Chuckles ]
It's just a big, gigantic
infomercial, folks.
[ Laughs ]
When I think of anybody
that's ever taken
what "Triple D" has given them
and run with it,
it has been you.
Menu expansion,
the location expansion.
I mean, just all these things
that you put together.
You really deserve it.
Well done, my friend.
Well done.
Thank you.
And this right here,
since nobody knows about it?
I'll take
a couple to go.
[ Chuckles ]
GUY:
And coming up, we're not keeping
anything under wraps anymore.
There's juices just running
out of this thing.
Because this corner joint
in Cambridge, Massachusetts
is proving
to be a place to party.
And the meat
disco ball starts.
Back in 2010,
I found this little spot
on a street corner
in Cambridge, Massachusetts,
dishing out Greek classics,
and it was,
well, music to my ears.
[ Angelic flute music plays ]
These days, they're still
singing the same tune.
Moussaka.
This is Greek Corner.
Salt fish kebab.
If you want authentic Greek food
in the Boston area,
this is the place
to come.
The food here
is always amazing.
People here really care
about the place.
WOMAN: The way that
George and Themis
came off on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives"
is how they are
in real life.
That'd be the Boretos brothers,
Georgios and Themis,
who have been cooking up
their cultural cuisines
for over 30 years.
The number-one dish
you do here?
I'll answer that for you.
The gyro.
We make the gyro together.
Excellent time.
Tell me
you are not excited.
Starting with the big piece,
go like this,
like this, so it's even.
He's making a gigantic
Tetris of meat.
Just doing lamb and beef,
and beef, beef, lamb.
♪ Lamb and beef,
lamb, beef, beef, beef ♪
♪ Lamb, beef,
beef, beef ♪
♪ Beef, beef,
[ Laughs ]
My brother,
he's a good singer,
but Guy, I think,
is a little better.
♪ Lamb-a, lamb-a, lamb-y,
lamb-y, lamb-y ♪
Beef, beef,
beef, beef.
You got to get
our new album.
We have "Lamb-a, Lamb-a,
Beef, Beef,"
and then
we also have...
Have pork and pig.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, so we're carving it
to make it uniform.
We took all the trimmings
and put them right down,
and the big pieces
drape over it.
So now we go
all the way up.
We put this fat on top
to keep the meat moist,
and then we put the onion
to give flavor.
Oh, that's gorgeous!
Meat disco ball
starts.
Okay, it's been on
for 30 minutes.
I'm gonna
give you one.
Oh, I like the way
that's going.
We have little olive oil
and oregano,
and we warm up the pita.
Look how uniform the layers are.
Lamb, lamb, beef, beef.
Lamb, lamb.   Lamb, lamb,
beef, beef.
Oregano with tzatziki.
Cucumbers, dill, lemon,
salt and pepper.
Beautiful.
Tomatoes, onions,
a little parsley,
and a little lettuce.
And now, ready.
Mmm. There's juices just
running out of this thing.
The crunch
and the mess.
You've not had
anything like this.
This is a real
meat attack.
If I say
"lamb, lamb,"
you say...
Beef, beef.
Do you not
know the song?
Pork, pork.
[ Laughs ]
After "Triple D,"
everybody was singing,
"Lamb, Lamb,
Beef, Beef,"
coming inside,
trying the gyro.
GUY: But they're also sinking
into their teeth into this one.
Now we're making
the baked lamb.
It's one of
the most popular dishes.
First thing we're gonna do
is searing the lamb
to keep the juices
in the meat.
While this is browning,
we're gonna start the onions.
We're gonna add
our special Greek wine,
and I always
keep some for myself.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're ready to add
the lamb in the pan.
Tomato puree
and tomato paste.
We use very nice,
fresh tomatoes.
We do that because we don't
want to use the outside.
Now, we're gonna
add cinnamon sticks,
salt, cloves,
bay leafs,
black pepper, water.
Stir it a little bit.
Cover it, and let it cook
for around three hours.
Here is our baked lamb.
The lamb bake
is just really flavorful.
It kind of melts
right off the bone.
The sear is perfect
because it's just enough
to hold the juices in,
and the meat literally
falls off the bone.
We were busy here,
but when "Triple D" came,
our business doubled.
We had a lot of people coming
from all over the United States.
GUY:
And the Corner got crowded,
not just with customers,
but with even more
Greek classics.
Look at that.
It's classic
pastichio.
You get the clove,
the cinnamon.
It all comes through.
This is Greek 101 right here.
WOMAN: Very traditional.
Simple flavors.
But made over time,
like moussaka.
It is on the menu
from the first day, 32 years.
We start building up
the moussaka with the potatoes.
We fry them,
and then bake them for an hour,
so they don't become
potato puree.
Now we're gonna add
the eggplant,
then the meat.
GEORGIOS: We start it with
extra virgin olive oil.
From Italy?
From Greece.
Oh.
Because we have
better oil.
Onions, fresh garlic,
bay leaves, pepper,
cinnamon sticks,
cloves.
Now we can
add the meat.
So brown all
the meat up?
Break it apart.
Now, we'll continue
with fresh tomatoes.
That's Italian
probably tomatoes.
[ Laughs ]
Tomato paste or puree?
Puree.
We stir it,
and we leave it until it's
cooked together with the meat.
And now, we're going to
add it to the pan,
distributing the meat even,
and then the bechamel sauce.
Now it's ready to go to the oven
for 50 minutes, 350 degrees.
And we're gonna cut it,
we serve it with rice.
Moussaka ready!
It's really delicious.
It's sort of a comfort food.
Soft and creamy on top.
It really blends well
with the warm spices underneath.
Awesome job.
Let me put
my glasses this way.
It's just
like that, see?
Oh, okay,
I understand.
Let me see.
See?
Yeah.
I'm doing good.
That's looking good.
We teach him, give him
a little Italian style.
Rocking the backwards shades
might be Greek to them,
but I got to tell you,
those brothers have me yearning
for the gyro.
Now coming up outside
of Baltimore...
Tacos al pastor!
...a tricky to find
taqueria...
Have you seen anything
more ridiculous?
...taking the city by storm.
Mmm. This is
the real deal.
Here's one
for the books.
Back in 2011,
I stopped outside
of Baltimore to gas up the '68,
and I find this
crazy Mexican place
where I could fuel up, too.
Outstanding.
Now they're filling up
their fans with three locations.
This is R&R Taqueria.
♪♪
Tacos al pastor!
I've had Mexican food
many times,
but never like this.
Chicken margarita,
ready!
WOMAN: We actually found out
about the gas station tacos
from "Triple D."
We knew we needed
to check it out.
GUY: And that's when I met
pilot turned chef
Rodrigo Albarron-Torres.
You were a flight instructor,
commercial pilot,
and then you decided to come
and open R&R Taqueria
next to a gas station
in Elkridge?
Something like that.
It's a story you hear
every day, Joe.
Heck, that's how I started
in the business.
GUY: A story so crazy,
I had to have a witness,
and who better
than legendary quarterback
and sports commentator,
Joe Theismann?
"Triple D" comes,
and the icing on the cake,
of course, Joe Theismann.
That was just incredible.
You watch football?
Oh, yeah, I love football.
Are you a Redskin
or Baltimore fan?
Colts.
Colts. Colts?
You made
a big turn, huh?
What are
we making first?
So, we're gonna work
on the al pastor.
This is a pork butt.
I know pork butt.
That's my middle name,
is Pork Butt.
Slice it first.
Start it out thin.
What he does is he takes it
and slices it
just a little bit,
then grabs it, peels it off.
What you do is you get a nice,
even cut like that,
and that's what it looks like
when you're slicing this.
It's really good.
Good stuff.
This is the "Triple D"
telestrator.
That is awesome.
So, guajillo chilies.
This is for
the pastor sauce.
Let this steep
in the warm water,
then into the blender
with all the ingredients?
Yes.
Oregano.
Thyme leaves.
You're getting
in his way.
Garlic.
I'm helping.
I'm an assistant.
Pineapple.
Pepper. Cinnamon.
Now we're taking the guajillos
and the chili de arbol,
and a little bit
of that pepper water.
You got to
save that.
Mixing up all of the pork,
the onions.
How long
does it marinate?
We usually
marinate for a day.
So, a little
of the pastor.
Whoa! Parmesan
in Mexican food?
Yeah.
Okay.
Pastor sauce,
and avocado.
Wow.
It's outstanding.
This is the real deal.
The meat is tender,
and the cheese sort of melts
in your mouth.
And then the avocado
gives it a nice freshness.
The salsa gives you that little
bit of, my nose is running.
[ Chuckles ]
You hear that? Do you hear that?
Listen.
[ Crickets chirping ]
Yep. What you just heard
is Guy Fieri's career ending.
[ Sad trombone plays ]
You're the man.
My buddy.
GUY:
But Rodrigo's not stopping
with his real-deal dishes.
We're gonna be
doing tlacoyos.
It's a very authentic
Mexican dish.
We're gonna make
our cactus salad.
Clean them up and just grab
a knife like this.
Chopped onions,
chopped tomatoes,
cilantro, red onions,
lime juice,
salt, pepper.
Start mixing it up.
Now this is ready
for our its tlacoyos.
We did something like that
in the episode.
It's called huaraches.
It's with the regular masa.
You want to get this
just to the right point.
Nice and light
and fluffy.
Yes. Refried beans.
Make your cup,
fill it, fold it.
That looks like
a little football.
But this one is the blue masa,
and black refried beans.
Grab some steak.
Green sauce, red sauce.
We got our steak, cactus salad,
Mexican cotija cheese.
This is your tlacoyo.
Tlacoyos,
Table 14.
Blue corn tortillas adds
a whole new dimension.
Cactus -- really tasty.
It's incredible to have
the beans
actually mixed in
with the masa.
It's a really
unique treat.
About to do
some lamb tacos.
We're gonna chop it up
and roast the whole thing.
Count the legs.
One...
What, like we took some?
Was this the three-legged lamb?
Is this the one?
This is
the real key.
These banana leaves, man,
this is the way to go.
This was your plastic
wrap in Mexico.
Now you're gonna
hit it with foil?
Foil.
And then it's good to go?
And then it's good to go.
Great.
I'm gonna get
the lamb out.
You looked at me when you said
to get the lamb out.
Here.
Give me this.
You ready?
I got you.
Ouch.
I just burned my hand.
Okay, it's good.
Ready?
It's just amazing how we're
trying to get that thing out.
It's heavy.
I got it.
Where are you going?
THEISMANN: No, we've got
to get the handle.
I've got flip-flops.
This is not good.
Watch your --
Alright?
[ Exhales sharply ]
It took three of us just to get
the lamb out of the oven.
Have you seen anything
more ridiculous?
Thank you
very much.
What do you do
when we're not here?
It's a big lamb.
It is a big lamb.
Are you ready?
This is it.
Look at that
THEISMANN:
Oh, wow.
I dip the tortilla a little bit
in the pasilla sauce.
Put a little bit
of the lamb.
We're gonna
roll it.
The next one --
sour cream.
You're gonna have to fight me
for this one, big guy.
Is this what it tastes like
when you were a kid?
Yes.
Just like it.
I never would have
left Mexico.
[ Chuckles ]
GUY:
But thankfully for us, he did,
bringing along
his grandmother's cookbook.
Chile rellenos.
This is one of my favorites.
It reminds me so much of
my grandma and going back home.
It's a poblano pepper, grill it,
stuff it up with cheese
and some queso frescos,
flour, and dip it
in the egg whites.
Cook this 'til
it's nice and golden.
And now we're gonna put
our ranchero sauce
right on top of it.
Tomato, jalapeños, garlic,
onions, chicken base, salt.
And then we're gonna
simmer the sauce.
Here's our chile relleno.
The chile relleno.
WOMAN: The cheese is
a nice, airy cheese,
and the pepper
is lightly battered.
Good tomato-y flavors,
peppery flavors.
MAN:
I'd heard about the taco place
in the gas station
for years from friends,
and I was like,
"Yeah, this is really
good Mexican food."
What was so attractive about
being right in a gas station?
Realize it's not the location,
it's really the food.
After the show,
next door open up.
So, we went from six stools
inside a gas station
to 120 seats.
We just kind of stepped
it up one more notch.
Wrap it up, Joe.
We got to go.
Don't bother me.
I'm eating.
Rodrigo,
you're the man.
Thank you.
Stepped it up a notch?
That's an understatement.
Stepped up his taco game
by leaving
the gas station behind
with three new joints,
not one of them with a pump.
And Stretch in Kansas City,
whose secret subs
and head-shaking shenanigans
can be found all over town.
Plus, the Boretos brothers
in Cambridge,
still making a mean moussaka.
And there are more of these
places blowing up
all over the country,
and we'll be checking them out
next time on "Triple D Nation."
I want to be, like,
Cheez Whiz wrestling.
Come on.
Get the Speedo out,
get that
Cheez Whiz going.
Ah.
I don't want to even
envision you
in Cheez Whiz wrestling going on
in the backyard.