Hey, there.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Whoa!
...we're cruising into creative
culinary creations.
This is outrageous.
Like boundary-pushing biscuits
in Virginia.
You're the biscuit king?
Dough daddy.
The dough daddy.
FIERI: Childhood favorites
gone wild in Vermont.
It sounds like a college
dorm-room concoction.
And in Ottawa, Canada...
Dude.
...a spot smashing up
both sweet...
This is
a destination doughnut.
...and savory.
I'm just 100% letting you know
I'm stealing this.
♪♪
I'm into history,
I'm into the old school,
into the nostalgia and I love
to see that it's coming back.
People are getting
into the cars,
the way they're dressing,
the way they're cooking.
So I'm here on the Old North End
of Burlington, Vermont,
where two gals
are taking it old school.
You're gonna dig it.
This is Butch & Babe's.
Flipping cakes.
On a scale of zero to legit...
It's on legit?
Just delicious.
The Big Butch.
WOMAN: All those flavors that
you know and love,
but they shake it up
a little differently.
FIERI: That offbeat menu
is brought to life
by Chef Jaclyn Major,
and that funky vibe
is a throwback
to owner Kortnee Bush's
family business.
FIERI:
Butch and Babe's?
That's my grandparents.
They were in banquets
and catering
for about 40 years
in Chicago.
So, you do this, and what
kind of restaurant is it?
An eclectic,
neighborhood hangout.
What is the menu,
Chef?
Produce-driven,
grandma chic.
Oh, whoa, whoa,
back up a second.
There's, like, millions
of cookbooks of that.
I like to make old-school,
classic dishes
with my own modern twist.
I got Mac and cheese pancakes
with hot dog.
Mac and cheese pancake
is ridiculous.
The crispiness that comes out
from the melted cheese
is beyond favorite.
Let's talk about
what we're making.
Well, we're gonna start
with the buttermilk
pancake batter.
Well, I guess we do.
I guess we do. Ready?
I mean, it's gonna be tough
to keep up with this one,
I can already tell you.
Flour, salt, baking soda.
I could probably leave
and you could just host
the rest of the show
by yourself if you want.
Kind of.
Eggs, buttermilk and, Guy,
we're just mixing
the pancake batter.
Are you still doing it?
Alright, she's doing
a great job, folks.
Diners, drive-ins,
and grandma recipes show.
Yes.
What's up next?
Habanero syrup.
Habanero syrup?
Vermont maple syrup,
grade A,
dark color, robust taste.
We might be related.
I know.
Alright, so maple syrup
and the habanero.
Bring it up to a boil.
We let it sit
for about three hours.
We've got a bucket of wieners,
bucket of mac,
bucket of Vermont cheddar.
Okay.
Buttermilk pancake batter,
hot-dog slices,
we're gonna put in
cooked elbow macaroni,
our Vermont cheddar,
press it down.
I'm impressed.
Spray the top of our pancakes
with nonstick spray.
Flip them over on the cheese.
You're making a gigantic skirt,
you're getting all
that crunchy cheese.
Scallion, habanero maple,
and we enjoy it.
♪♪
This is outrageous.
The crunchy part
and the creamy part
of the mac and cheese.
It's the saltiness of something
you don't get enough of,
which is hot dog,
and then you dip it over here
into a slightly spicy
Vermont maple.
It's all
my favorite things.
It sounds like the weirdest
thing I've seen
on a menu in a long time,
and it is so legit.
Well done.
Whoa!
Wow,
that was a hot snap.
Hot dog
mac and cheese pancakes.
You get the sweet, you get
the spicy, you get the tangy.
It's killer.
It sounds like a college
dorm-room concoction.
Sunshine board in the window.
WOMAN #2: Butch & Babe's
is a great
Burlington restaurant.
It's real deal.
It's the real deal.
She always uses
local ingredients.
Mmm.
We're not gonna be able
to talk
between your wows
and your mmm's.
I don't know if I'm supposed
to talk about this,
but I'm actually
a vegetable farmer.
What, is there, like,
some secret
vegetable-farmer cult?
Shh.
Jackie is one of the few chefs
I know who will say,
"Just give me a surprise box
of whatever's in season,"
and she makes it work.
Four Elote dogs,
in the window.
Elote dog's a nice corn dog.
It's like that classic,
Mexican corn
with all that good cheese on it.
Fair food brought up
about 100 notches.
So, guess what we're
gonna make next.
Corn dog batter?
Corn dog batter,
right here.
We start
with gluten-free flour,
cornmeal, cornstarch.
We're gonna put
some eggs in there.
Okay.
Sugar.
Honey.
Baking powder and milk.
Corn dogs inside
of a restaurant?
Somebody can come and get
a really fancy,
produce-driven meal
or a corn dog.
[ Laughter ]
So we're gonna make
our magic sauce.
Okay, why does it look
like we're making mayonnaise?
Because we have to make
mayonnaise first.
Eggs, Dijon mustard,
white vinegar,
raw garlic,
a little salt, start her up.
And we slowly drizzle
in our oil.
Okay, so that's the beginning
of magic sauce. What next?
Lime juice, lime zest
is really good.
Jalapeño,
we've roasted those.
Smoked onions,
smoked paprika, sriracha.
Thimble of sriracha?
Yep, a thimble of sriracha,
a little bit more garlic,
and our house mayonnaise.
Do you have a second?
Look here.
We're gonna need folks
to call into the number below
on your screen.
We're starting
the Gofundme right now.
Now we'll add our sour cream
to it.
We're looking for it
to be kind of like crema,
but also kind of
like the mayonnaise
you would get
on Mexican street corn.
Magic sauce.
The smokiness
reigned supreme in that.
It does.
Let's make that dog.
Natural-casing hot dog.
Look at that tacky batter.
We drop it.
Drop it like it's...
Hot.
Thank you.
We're gonna take our hot
Elote dog,
magic sauce
we just made,
queso fresco, Elote spice
that has cumin, coriander,
paprika, cayenne,
and salt.
Pickled onions, cilantro.
That's it.
I want you to think about
the crispiest,
lightest batter,
delicious snap of a hot dog,
served with a balance
of accoutrements.
It's just a really
composed corn dog.
[ Laughs ]
From the cheese
to the pickled onions
to the magic sauce,
it's really executed right.
If you could pop in here,
have that,
and get a cold beer,
you're set for the day.
Elote Dog.
It is a very fun dish to eat.
Stupendous.
Stupendous, even.
You enjoyed your lunch?
It was so good.
This is an incredibly
cool restaurant.
Just a fun, fun place to be.
FIERI: You put some
of the techniques
back into some
of the old-school recipes,
you really get these things
that you're like,
"Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa."
You're a force
to be reckoned with.
Great job.
FIERI:
Up next in Richmond, Virginia...
If you want to have
your life changed,
this is where you come.
We're changing lives.
...a joint loading up
the biscuits.
THOMPSON: We should sell it
with pajama pants.
Or a Snuggie.
...and putting a new twist
on tots.
This is kind of illegal,
I would think.
♪♪
You know, at "Triple D,"
we have been to restaurants
that have been dedicated
to one type of food,
like a pizza joint
or places that are dedicated
only to hot dogs
or only to burgers or only
to sandwiches, only to barbecue.
You get my idea, right?
I'm here in Richmond, Virginia,
and I've heard about a place
that's all about the biscuit.
They call this area The Fan,
and this is The Fancy Biscuit.
The Fancy Biscuit's all about
the biscuit done right.
And it's really inventive.
Big Apple, order up.
FIERI: This concept
comes from the combo
of artist Nicole Jessee
and her restaurant-bent husband,
Bryon.
BRYON: When Nicole
and I had the idea
of doing
the biscuit restaurant,
we're like,
"We need William."
So they got him -- their chef
and pal William Thompson.
You're the biscuit king?
Dough daddy.
The dough daddy.
Walking out, Black Dog.
The Black Dog is the best shrimp
and grits I've had.
So shrimp and grits
meets a biscuit,
all piled up high.
Yes, and it's perfection.
Why is it called
the Black Dog?
There was a black dog
that kind of roamed
the streets around here.
So homage to the dog
is that we named
a biscuit after him.
Must have been
some kind of special dog.
Alright, so a great biscuit
starts with?
White Lily Flour.
Okay.
Cold vegetarian shortening.
Got it.
It's gonna cut up to about
pea-size pieces of fat here.
Cold buttermilk,
salt and pepper.
Bring this together.
I'm gonna fold it.
How many times you
gonna layer that?
Four layers.
Can't see that he's ever done
this before, right?
Go straight down
and straight up. Do not twist.
There you go.
375 degrees
for 16 minutes.
Butter these bad boys up.
Beautiful.
We're gonna make
the Tasso ham gravy.
First is gonna be
our ghee.
Clarified butter.
Shallots.
Okay.
Tasso ham.
Tasso ham
right in there.
Flour here.
Make your roux.
House-made chicken stock,
heavy cream, salt and pepper.
Once this gravy comes together,
the toppings await.
Good, good, good.
We're gonna start
with more ghee,
Tasso ham,
shallots, shrimp.
That's a lot of shrimp
for a biscuit.
Garlic, fresh lemon juice,
some shrimp butter.
Okay.
Add our gravy.
Now it's ready to plate.
Got it.
Scoop of grits,
pour a whole bunch there.
This is kind of illegal,
I would think.
Love the Tasso, love the big
grits, flaky biscuit,
gravy's not heavy,
not too salty.
This is definitely
a rainy Sunday dish.
I eat that in the middle of
week, I'll be asleep here.
Yeah, we should sell it
with pajama pants.
Or a Snuggie.
Even better.
Right up my alley.
Well done.
Black Dog
working in the pan.
The biscuits
are light and fluffy.
The shrimp is tender
and delicious.
I mean, they have made
the biscuit trendy.
FIERI: Which is par for the
course on this side of town.
MAN: The Fan is a neighborhood
that is a staple of Richmond,
everybody knows what it is.
The Fancy Biscuit,
it's such a wonderful addition.
It's got a real Southern vibe.
THOMPSON: Plating grit tots.
I love the ham and cheese grit,
fried into a tot.
WOMAN #3: Who doesn't love
when you fry something
that's already amazing?
They're really good.
Alright, chef.
What are we gonna get into?
THOMPSON: Our Tasso ham
and cheddar grit tots.
We're gonna start
with chicken stock
that we put in our grits.
Some chicken bones,
cold water here, mirepoix.
I got to sauté this baby
with bay leaf.
Parsley, thyme.
Garlic and peppercorn.
Tri-color, got it.
And then I get a string.
Where's your string?
In your pocket.
Okay.
Chest pocket.
Nope.
No?
Your chest pocket.
My chest pocket.
That's what you meant.
If you had a magic trick
and that was
in my chest pocket,
we were gonna have
a whole different show.
Boom. This is gonna cook down
for about two hours now.
Now, look at those,
those are some
stone ground right there.
That's right.
No instant down here.
Now, come on now.
No self-respecting
Southerner, right?
Extra virgin olive oil,
some Tasso ham.
Tasso Ham. Shallots.
We're gonna add
our homemade chicken stock.
A little bit
of heavy cream.
Now, were you making grits
before you worked here?
Being in the South,
it's one of those things
you do when you grow up.
You better know how.
I think you've got to do it
to graduate eighth grade.
Stone-ground grits. Now, you
can't walk away from this.
You can't walk away
from this.
It'll burn to the bottom.
It'll burn it to the bottom.
Then you fail
the eighth grade.
You go back
all the way to kindergarten.
Salt and pepper.
Probably gonna take
about an hour.
Well, you have a good time.
I'll be right back.
I'm gonna go
check the car.
Thank you.
Keep it up. Doing good.
Guy, we're ready!
I'm making grits with this dude.
I got to go.
Talking to my kid about grits.
He's a big grit fan.
So this is gonna be
some extra-sharp cheddar cheese.
I need to do this
in the name of science.
The grind on this
is so big.
You're getting
really big pieces.
Lots of texture.
That's grits.
We're gonna add it
to a sheet tray.
Let it cool.
Cut these in about
one-inch dices.
Okay.
This is just some regular
old flour.
Fry them for about
three minutes.
Drain them off. Throw them
right in here like this.
Our sriracha aioli,
some green onion.
That's a wrap.
♪♪
So for a guy who likes grits,
creamy,
good amount of cheese,
great texture to the grit.
The Tasso's really nice.
Good little salt to that.
Not oily by any means.
Not too much breading.
If you like grits or polenta,
you're gonna love that.
Well done, man.
MAN:
The grit tots are incredible.
I only eat grits
in this form now.
If you want to have
your life changed,
this is where you come.
We're changing lives.
The clouds open up.
The angels are singing.
What are you drinking?
THOMPSON: Got Your Goat,
two minutes out.
Chef William,
you're a good dude, man.
Thank you very much.
Watch out.
Don't hang out with this guy.
You're gonna gain
20 pounds.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up
in Ottawa, Canada...
Ah!
...an artful
bakery/restaurant...
You are definitely
an artist.
...sculpting
a doughnut-croissant combo.
Delicious.
...and a pasta-pizza
masterpiece.
You went right off
the rails, captain.
♪♪
So I'm here in the Little
Italy of Ottawa.
Can you say it five times fast?
Little Italy of Ottawa,
Little Italy --
Alright. I can only get two.
Anyhow, back in the '50s,
this was a big old grain depot.
Now it's home
to a bunch of businesses.
One in particular
is a restaurant with a chef
who studied down in the States,
studied back in Paris
and now he's doing
wholesale bakery,
retail bakery and a restaurant.
Oh, this place is huge.
Not just in size, but in flavor.
This is Art Is In.
Eggs Benny Avocado, please.
Art Is In is creative,
well-executed.
Pickle melt here.
Everything they make is
a work of art.
FIERI: And the artist is chef
and owner Kevin Mathieson,
who's throwing both sweet
and savory creations
onto his culinary canvas.
So you're a bakery.
Yes.
And then you're also
a restaurant.
Yes. We make everything
from scratch,
like we do lots
of Viennoiserie.
Yeah, that's what
I was gonna say.
I have no clue
what that is.
-Four O-Towners.
-Oh, the O-Towner.
It's a pastry bigger
than your head.
Creamy.
Extremely decadent.
Delicious.
So what are we
gonna make, Chef?
Some O-Towners.
So it's a cross between
a doughnut and a croissant.
So a croissant's not
good enough by itself.
And a doughnut's
not good enough by itself.
Absolutely not.
So we're gonna make like
a liger,
right here on "Triple D."
I'm adding some whole milk,
eggs, fresh yeast,
shortening, some flour,
pastry flour, sugar, salt.
This is gonna mix
for about four minutes.
We're gonna let it
sit in the fridge
and then we're
gonna laminate it.
Where's the sign that says
"No long clothing"?
MATHIESON: And we have our
beautiful butter here.
It's just like a little fun
little package.
Give it a couple of wacks.
Make sure
that it stays together
when it goes through
the lamination.
Give it
four double folds.
-And a half double back flip.
-Yep.
FIERI: Do we get
to reuse this dough?
Yeah, we do lots
with this dough.
That was a big dilemma
in the beginning.
Big dilemma.
How many layers
do you think that really is?
24 times 4.
Hang on, I've got to get
my shoe off,
I've got to count that high.
It's about 100 layers.
So these proof up.
And what temp are
we gonna fry at?
400.
They've got to be very hot.
They build a crust
on the outside quickly,
otherwise they can
slinky around.
Can you put some EDM music
to that, please?
Now we're in
the pistachio cream.
Yes. So we're gonna make
a general custard.
In France, they call
it creme patisserie.
It doesn't sound nearly
as cool as general custard.
Milk.
Vanilla?
Vanilla bean,
pure pistachio paste,
sugar, cornstarch,
yolks,
and I'm gonna temper
the hot cream into here.
Into this. Got it.
And then add it all back
to the pot
and bring it to a boil.
Finish it with butter.
And that's what
we're gonna pipe.
Into the O-Towner.
Hot out of the fryer.
Dude, it's gorgeous.
Roll them
in cinnamon sugar.
You see the finger roll
with the "brr"?
I make a hole
on three parts
and then we fill it
with our pistachio
pastry cream.
Don't tell me
you're gonna flip this
and do the raspberry
on the other side.
The French call it a gelee,
but I call it a jam.
Sacre bleu.
Top with
raspberry pearls.
I don't even like sweets.
My mouth's drooling.
I don't know
what to do with this.
People eat it
in many different ways.
I want
to bite it like this,
but it's gonna get
half of the jam up my nose.
I'm gonna jam the jam.
I'm gonna be on
the rowing machine
for a week with this.
♪♪
Is there any on my face?
You are good.
You're not being very nice.
Delicious.
You know what you need
is an eyewash kit.
How am I looking there?
Bob in Saskatchewan?
Awesome. It's not as sweet
as I anticipated.
The execution
is masterful.
The balance of flavor
is really well orchestrated.
I don't want to say
you get a saltiness
of the pistachio cream,
but it's not a heavy sugar.
It's a rich, earthy,
nuttiness...
balanced with the sweet tang
from the raspberry
and then a little bit of
that cinnamon coming through,
but it's the light,
fluffy layers
of the lacquered
doughnut, bro.
I'm the least dessert guy
you've ever seen
and that's probably
the most doughnut
I've eaten
in the last 40 years.
This is
a destination doughnut.
One of the best
I've ever had.
Pistachio raspberry
O-Towners are up.
The pastry cream is perfect.
Little bit of salty, some sweet.
Something like 80 layers.
100,
but I'm not counting it.
Maybe it's 80% butter
and 100 layers.
It's 80% kitchen and 20%
dining room is what it is.
-Croque madame up.
-How many square feet is this?
MATHIESON: This is
about 3,500 square feet.
Dude. What's over there?
Our kitchen.
All that kitchen is
for that dining room
or is there like
an 8,000-person
banquet hall upstairs?
I wish.
Art Is In is a very well-known
place here in Ottawa.
This is flavor dome.
I only came here for
the breakfast and the pastries
and then I found out
about the pizzas.
FIERI: And this joint
isn't just laying down
regular pizza toppings.
Spaghetti with a chance
of meatballs.
MAN #2: You've got this mountain
of spaghetti in the middle.
You look at it and you go,
"Oh, my gosh,
we're gonna have fun here."
Now I've had a half pound
of sugar,
when we come back,
we're hanging out over here.
We're gonna make
spaghetti pizza.
We'll see you in a little bit.
Alright, let's go.
FIERI: Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in little Italy, Ottawa.
We're at Art Is In.
His name's not Art
and he is in,
but it's artisan.
FIERI:
His name is actually Kevin,
and he's the master behind
the pieces of culinary art
at this bakery and restaurant.
Two spaghetti with
a chance of meatballs.
WOMAN #4: You're not gonna get
anything like spaghetti
with a chance of meatballs
anywhere else in Ottawa.
MAN #2: Spaghetti's
in the middle
and you've got the nice crust.
Best pizza around.
Alright, so let's make
the dough first.
Right. Water.
I'm gonna add the starter.
How long has this starter
been living?
Eight years.
Someone killed the starter once.
And they don't work here
anymore.
Baker's flour.
It's about a 14% protein flour,
so it's elastic-y.
Organic whole wheat flour,
tiny bit of yeast, salt.
Got it.
Mix the dough
for four minutes.
Let it rise
for an hour and a half.
Fold. I'm gonna let it sit
for another two hours
and then we fold it again.
Then we let it sit
another hour
and then we can process it
into pizza dough.
I can't even keep up.
I'm reading the story
and get up tomorrow
and had a good morning.
And then we shape it
per order for every pizza.
Of course.
Yes.
Pesto is up.
Olive oil, lemon juice,
garlic, walnuts,
Parmigiano-Reggiano,
salt and pepper,
some parsley,
basil, arugula adds
this pepperiness to it.
I dig it.
I'm just 100% letting you know
I'm stealing this.
It's all yours.
Light on the garlic,
heavy on the herbs.
Love the arugula. Wow, man.
Thank you.
Last but not least,
the meatballs.
So I have
some ground veal,
a house-ground beef chuck,
our bread crumbs.
This is made
from our pretzels.
Raw onion,
Parmigiano-Reggiano,
some nutmeg, oregano,
pepper, salt, garlic.
Nice.
Some parsley, two eggs.
A little binder.
Do you think you can add
a little bit of the cream?
Oh, oh, I'm sorry.
Let those bread crumbs
absorb some of the moisture.
These go
on the pizza raw.
As it cooks, all that stays
on the pizza
and builds the flavor.
I mean, he...
this guy...
Beautiful tender dough.
Build the edge.
You're gonna start
winging that thing
and I'm gonna start
wearing flour.
And I don't wear white
after Labor Day.
Look at all
that yeast activity. Ah!
MATHIESON: Yes. Brush the crust
with some olive oil.
Sesame seeds.
Didn't sesame seed
that coming.
This sauce has been sitting
in the oven all night
long with garlic
and fresh thyme.
Now the meatballs,
but we're gonna cook this
without cheese first.
Yes, 650.
The anticipation
is killing me.
Now, the cheese going on
is...?
MATHIESON:
Whole-milk mozzarella.
Back in the oven.
How long?
Two minutes.
Which one do you want?
Big one.
And we will do the spaghetti
with our Nonna sauce.
Tomato with butter
and onion.
Pasta down.
Basil. You cut the pizza
in the strips.
Right off the rails,
captain.
Put the spaghetti in this ladle.
Try to give it some height.
Parmigiana-Reggiano
on the crust, long red chilies.
And yet there's more.
Basil and then pesto.
I don't know how to attack it.
I mean, look at it.
♪♪
It's like I've never
eaten before.
Boy, that crust
is delicious.
Meatballs are super tender,
nice creamy cheese.
♪♪
The freshness of the pesto
is that little break
that you need,
but this is what we're talking
about right here, folks.
Pasta that would rival
any great Italian restaurant.
You have pushed
all the boundaries, my friend.
You're a dangerous man.
Spaghetti with a chance
of meatballs up.
The kids love it.
We all love it.
It's an experience
in and of itself.
Four croque monsieurs.
MAN #2: It's hard to get that
combination of something
that looks great as well
as tastes great,
and Art Is In does it
every single time.
You are definitely an artist
and your medium is food.
Ah, thanks so much.
Dude's the real deal.
Out of bounds.
♪♪
There we go.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪