Hey there, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
It's everything you want.
...which is all kinds of
savory...
One small bite for man.
...served with
a side of sweet...
Someone's going to have
a little bit of a sugar problem
here in a second.
...like funky cheese
and a cinnamon chaser in Utah...
Things are getting weird.
...loaded lasagna...
Whoa!
...and cream puff mountains
in Colorado...
How do you attack it?
...plus Vermont vegan...
It's "Get on a plane and come
to Vermont" remarkable.
...wrapped, crunched,
and puffed.
Outstanding experience.
That's all right here,
right now on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Wheat Ridge,
just west of Denver, Colorado.
Now, let me just tell you,
back in the day,
I first started
working at the fair
selling my pretzels
at The Awesome Pretzel cart,
and then when I got
my restaurants,
well, I started selling
what I'd sell
at the restaurant at the fair.
But I heard about this family
that started off
in the fair business,
and then they went
and opened a restaurant.
This is Grammy's Goodies.
Chicken Alfredo
and a sausage cannoli.
Best Italian food in the city.
Giant ravioli for Mackenzie.
Coming to this place is like
going to your grandma's house.
FIERI:
Because Grammy's is actually
filled with grandma's recipes,
which Vickie Corder,
her husband Jeff,
and their kids first started
selling at festivals.
And when business boomed,
they expanded into
a full-fledged restaurant.
-What's the story?
-I needed a commissary
for our concession business.
We do 50 events a year
all over Colorado.
There's no way you are not
from Long Island.
-Every day...
-Every day.
...people tell me that.
New York looks like me.
See, that's it.
Jeff's original cannoli.
I feel like all the food here
is larger than life.
Sauce and lasagna.
FIERI:
Have you seen lasagna that big?
Not before, no.
It's the cheesiest lasagna
you'll ever eat.
What do we start with?
-My grandmother's Sunday sauce.
-Okay. Okay.
Olive oil, pork ribs,
and neck bones.
-Any prosciut'?
-No.
How did you know
what that was?
Because I'm Italian.
You call it prosciut'
in Denver?
I call it prosciutto because
I'm not...
BOTH: ...from New York.
-Garlic salt.
-What's up next?
She made us put everything
in the sauce in threes
because it blessed the sauce.
-Father...
-So, one garlic.
...Son, Holy Ghost.
That's a lot of garlic.
That's the perfect amount
of garlic.
I thought so, too.
That's what I meant to say.
Onion. Parsley.
What about the Father
and the Son?
I'm saying it to myself.
Oh! I want to be in on it.
Crushed tomatoes.
Fresh basil. Black pepper.
And salt.
Tomato paste goes in.
And a lot of water.
And how long
is this going to cook?
About three hours.
-What's up next?
-Nana's meatballs.
Is Nana different the Grammy?
No, I called her Grammy.
My kids called her Nana.
Nana.
It's half pork, half ground
beef, mix it together.
Now, she taught you
these recipes
by you standing next to her,
or did she just throw you
right in the mix?
She had horrible arthritis.
-Oh, really?
-So, I was her hands.
Chopped onions,
soft bread crumbs.
Basil, garlic.
You guys love your garlic.
Parsley, Romano cheese...
BOTH: Salt.
Black pepper and eggs.
How many meatballs
will this make?
About that tray's worth.
Okay, good.
They're about a third
of a pound.
Ooh, you really coat
the pan up, huh?
We're not just going to
bake 'em, we're gonna also
give 'em
a little pan fry.
350 degrees. How long?
-15 minutes.
-Next up?
Whole milk, ricotta cheese.
Okay.
Black pepper, eggs,
fresh parsley, mozzarella,
provolone blend,
and Romano cheese.
-How many layers you making?
-Probably six.
Okay. Just shout it out
when you know the answer.
You make me so nervous.
I'm just standing there talking.
Granted, I'm questioning...
The place of my origin.
Well, that we know
is just a gigantic farce.
Did you see her just try
to kick me on "Triple D"?
[ Laughs ]
All right, Vic.
Let's see it.
Olive oil.
We line our noodles up.
It's got to be seven by seven.
Sauce. About half the cheese
on this layer.
[ Whistles ]
How much of the sausage
is going in there?
All of it.
That's a lot of sausage.
The family that makes it
has been in business
for a hundred years.
They were friends
with my grandmother.
-Got it.
-Noodles.
Noodles again, sauce again,
cheese again.
-Meatballs.
Oh, this should be
an interesting number.
A lot of meatballs.
Well, that can't be
the real way, Vic.
It's 12. It's 12.
I think I'm being told a story.
12. Okay.
How many do
have it in there now?
I have no clue.
Me either.
Provolone, noodles.
How long is this going to bake?
Four years?
About three hours.
Whoa!
That is a monster.
Oh, the parsley
made it healthier.
Yeah.
Eat your vegetables.
One small bite for man.
[ Chuckles ]
So, I know that this is
the lasagna portion
for the entire family.
Lots of ricotta.
Delicious meatballs.
Tender pasta.
Dynamite sauce.
You make this roll
yourself also?
Yes.
Well, I'm going to
tell you what.
This is old school
American Italian.
Exactly the kind of lasagna
I would expect to go
get at Grammy's house.
Dynamite.
Lasagna for Lou.
In each bite you get
cheese and meat.
Just got hit
with the waterfall of sauce.
[ Laughs ]
So, this is my nephew, Daniel,
and he goes to college up here
with these cats.
Is this legit?
Legit as it gets.
FIERI:
Same with the desserts.
I come just for the sweet taste.
You want chocolate,
they've got chocolate.
If you want creamy,
they've got creamy.
This is the giant cream puff.
It's very good.
This is more whipped cream
than I've ever seen
in my entire life.
My sister says I can't eat it
in one sitting, but I can.
FIERI:
What is the dish we're making?
One pound cream puff.
I've got to go.
So, butter...
Butter.
...into boiling water.
Add your flour, salt.
And drop this in the mixture
with the eggs?
-Yes.
-All right.
So, the dough is now
in the piping bag.
How many of these
you make a week?
A ton.
No. See, I have to
take you literal with that
because a ton really could be
how many you make.
Could be a ton.
In the oven. 400 degrees.
How long?
About an hour.
What else is going to go
with this gigantic
85-pound cream puff?
My grandmother's
whipped cream recipe.
Of course it would be.
Heavy cream,
powdered sugar,
and vanilla?
Yes. Ta-da.
Look at that.
And then...
I'm dead.
...the top.
I do not know
what to do with it.
I mean, how do you attack it?
♪♪
The puff pastry
is so delicate.
It works as the perfect vessel.
It's light, it's fresh,
but the whipping cream
is not super sugary.
It's like
a Americanized cannoli.
It's got great texture to it.
There's a little bit of crunch
on the outside of this.
Vic, that's all you
need to sell.
[ Laughs ]
Cream puff for Dino.
Oh, delectable.
The crust is crunchy and flaky.
I will definitely take it home
for later.
Set up for the pizza.
It truly is the best food
in the city.
It's like we used
to eat at home.
You take every single
one of these,
like Grammy
would be sitting right here.
Yes.
You don't really follow rules of
keeping things in normal sizes?
No. You saw my husband.
Jeff was only two feet tall
when he started working here.
Nicely done. And she's not,
for the last time,
from Denver.
From New --
[ Laughs ]
Up next, a lights-out
vegan joint
in Burlington, Vermont...
-Oh!
-[ Laughs ]
...getting wild with a wrap.
That probably's in the top
five greatest vegetarian,
vegan items
I've ever had in my life.
...and having a ball
with French toast.
I got to be honest with you,
Chef, it is up here.
♪♪
I got to tell you,
the food revolution
is alive and well today.
You know, it's great to see
all these new styles of cooking
and these ethnicities
get recognized,
and one that's really emerging
the most is vegan/vegetarian.
Boy, wouldn't my sister
be so proud?
So, I'm here in Burlington,
Vermont, to check out a joint
where this guy's getting such
acclaim, people were saying
that he should be the driver
of the vegan bus to Flavortown.
This is Pingala.
♪♪
Table eight. Broccoli bites
and Crunchy Hippie.
There's something really special
about the food here.
Pressing tofu.
It just really makes vegan food
something everyone wants to eat.
It's almost one of those words
like, it's...
[ echoes ] vegan.
They look at this menu
and they're like, "Wow."
FIERI: That menu is the work
of Trevor Sullivan,
who's putting the healthy mantra
he lives by
right into his recipes.
Where's the name come from?
It's a Sanskrit word.
Pingala is a line of energy
that we all have in our bodies,
that means sun energy, and we're
doing all plant-based foods.
They have so many
amazing options
that are really creative
and delicious.
Runner.
Runner, crunch wrap, please.
The crunch wrap's this
ooey-gooey mess of awesomeness
with the beans, the queso,
and the rice inside this
crunchy flour tortilla
that's just toasted
and grilled to perfection.
What are we going to
make first?
We're going to do
the crunch wrap.
We get our chili going,
sunflower seed oil,
some fresh garlic,
mirepoix, serranos.
So, everything that we love
about a good chili.
Chili powder, cumin,
smoked paprika, cinnamon,
some salt,
a little brown sugar,
sweat that all together.
Okay.
Now add tomatoes,
organic tomato paste.
Tamari, give it a lot of depth.
Lentils.
I get mental with lentil.
Yeah, sentimental lentil?
Black beans.
All right, so how long we
going to let this cook down for?
An hour, hour and a half.
-What's up next?
-Not avocado mash.
Why do we not just
have avocados?
The prices of avocado kind of
went through the roof,
so we wanted to just
sort of mimic it
and make it something
different and unique.
So, we're going to make
some herb oil.
Fresh garlic, raw onion,
rosemary, sage,
tarragon, parsley, salt.
I'm going to get this going.
Emulsify with the oil.
Then it's ready to go
in the processor
with the chickpeas
and the peas.
Nutritional yeast, and then
last secret ingredient here,
a little lemon extract.
Blend this down.
Okay.
Take our herb oil. Voilà.
Look at it from here
and tell me it's not avocado.
♪♪
Bro...
[ Laughs ] Yeah.
The texture is spot-on.
Can I get this with
some chips and salsa?
Yeah, man.
That probably's in the top five
greatest vegetarian/vegan items
I've ever had in my life.
Oh!
Let's make some cashew cheese.
I'm willing to learn.
We'll start with
some soaked cashews,
sweet potato puree, yeast.
Nutritional yeast.
You got it.
Cayenne, oregano,
garlic powder,
some turmeric.
Great color from that.
A little salt, pepper,
and lemon juice.
And hot water.
You want to let this roll
for a little bit
until it gets nice
and smooth and creamy.
♪♪
It's outstanding.
It's creamy.
It's not over-salty.
It's not overpowering.
Love the little bit
of the lemon.
And the great thing is that
a little spice in there.
-Yeah.
-What's left?
Oat milk cheese.
So, boiling water.
Adding our rolled oats in.
How long is this going to cook?
Three to five minutes.
We're going to
get right in there.
Nutritional yeast again.
-Turmeric.
-Some garlic powder.
A little salt, lemon juice,
a little oil,
a little immersion
blender action.
Start adding in our tapioca.
Flour. Tighten it up.
♪♪
Dude, I'm so impressed.
Let's build this thing.
I'm dying.
All right.
Tortilla, oat cheese.
Brown rice?
Just seasoned up
a little special.
-Okay.
-Our chili, cashew cheese,
a couple crunchy tortillas
that we just toasted
in the oven.
Not avocado mash, tomato,
some scallion, cilantro,
some pickled jalapeño.
I'm not sure where
this is going.
This is going right in there.
Ooh!
We just fold it up,
press this on a panini press.
30 seconds, 45 seconds.
There's your crunch wrap.
♪♪
Bro, it's outstanding.
The textures, the seasoning.
The fake avocado...
Yeah.
...probably was the foundation
of me getting my mind blown.
I mean, out of
vegetarian/vegan dishes
I've had in my life,
this is easily
in the top five
if not top three.
♪♪
I would challenge anybody
who doesn't think
they like vegetarian/vegan
to come down here
and try this.
It's remarkable.
"Get on a plane and come
to Vermont" remarkable.
Crunch wrap.
I need a runner.
If you're a cheese lover,
this is the one to go to.
It's just comforting.
It's really yummy.
In a one to 10,
texture and flavor,
what would you give that?
I would definitely give it a 10.
ELT in the window.
I don't know where he comes up
with these ideas,
but they're always
incredible.
Never been to Vermont.
This is my first visit,
and this is who I meet?
FIERI:
And this is what he's making.
Sexy French toast.
The French toast puffs, they
almost taste like cake balls.
FIERI: Got to check this out
when we come back.
This isn't any French toast.
This is a Christmas cookie.
And to scoop this,
I got to add
a little bit more bread in.
Whew. Refreshing.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
So, welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Burlington, Vermont,
right on the...
Winooski.
...Winooski River at Pingala.
I come all the way to Vermont
and I find a vegan restaurant
where it's not
what you're expecting.
And I got to be honest with,
Chef, it is up here.
Runner, fresh rolls.
You don't remember that you're
eating a plant-based diet here.
Just feels like
you're eating food.
Two orders of French toast
coming up.
The French toast puffs
are everything you want
in French toast
that french toast
has never delivered
to me before.
You can dip them
in the syrup,
in the ginger butter.
It feels like dessert.
Now what are we into?
French toast.
We're basically making
a French toast bread pudding.
Bananas, oat milk,
brown sugar,
toasted coconut flakes,
vanilla extract, cinnamon.
So, the normal cast
of characters.
Pinch of salt. The turmeric
gives it that nice eggy color.
-Okay.
-Nutmeg going in.
[ Whirring ]
That's it.
And then we're going
to add it to our millet
and flaxseed bread.
This is going to start
to absorb it.
We scoop it.
I'm excited.
We're going to bake it
at 500 degrees
for about five
to eight minutes.
And what are we going
to serve it with?
Some ginger butter.
For this we use
a dairy free butter,
and we're going to add a agave,
some cinnamon,
some nutmeg,
ginger powder, pinch of salt.
We buzz this down.
Send it back
into the refrigerator.
Let it tighten back up.
Let it tighten up.
Mm-hmm.
Good stuff.
All right, we're going to
plate up some French toast.
We're going to take
a mixed berry coulis.
We just got some mixed berries,
lemon juice, and water.
Okay.
A little cinnamon, maple syrup,
ginger butter,
some banana, oranges.
Take our French toast puffs.
-How many do you get?
-Seven in heaven.
Well, who do you think's
with me?
[ Laughs ]
I drove up in the car by myself.
[ Sniffs ]
Smells like French toast.
Has better texture
than most French toast.
♪♪
I don't know what to say, bro.
This isn't any French toast.
This is a Christmas cookie.
It's everything you want.
It's got the cinnamon,
it's got the nutmeg,
it's got the sweet,
it's got the texture.
It's like banana bread
gone wild.
♪♪
My son Ryder would
go bananas for this.
Some French toast.
They taste even better
than the French toast
I remember as a kid.
I can't get enough.
It's got more flavor...
Texture.
...more freshness.
Just fabulous that it's also
healthy at the same time.
What he's doing?
Yeah.
Next level.
If I stopped being
vegan tomorrow,
I'd still enjoy
the food here.
Outstanding experience.
You're doing things
that are really out there
in terms of methods
and styles and textures
and flavors and seasonings.
Lions and tigers and bears.
Oh, my.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
If you're going to bring
your friends down here,
please don't tell them
it's vegan.
Let them have the "aha" moment.
Well done, Chef.
Yeah, thanks, Guy.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, a historic
spot in Logan, Utah...
You've got it going
there, buddy.
...rolling out a classic...
I want that one.
...and turning
grilled cheese inside out.
This is the weirdest
grilled cheese
we've ever seen on "Triple D."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Logan, Utah,
just a stone's throw away
from Utah State University
on old Highway 89.
[ Crickets chirp, coyote howls ]
You know what you find
on old Highway 89
down in a little
residential neighborhood?
You find an old building,
old building
that was vacant
for about 70 years
and was about to be torn down
until somebody says,
"No, I'm going to buy it,
I'm going to refurbish it,
and we're going to put
a restaurant in it."
This, I got to see.
Welcome to Herm's Inn.
♪♪
Stuffed French toast, table six.
Just turned it into
a fabulous place
for people
to come and dine.
I got rye down
for the Reuben.
The word's out.
Everyone in Logan
knows about Herm's.
People come from out of town
to come here.
FIERI: And they've done that
since the early 1900s,
because this historic building
has been a place for travelers
to sleep, eat,
and top off the tank.
But it sat abandoned
for decades
before a local businessman
saved it from the wrecking ball.
Mr. Laub,
who owns the building,
wanted to bring it
back to its heyday.
FIERI:
Which means general manager
Andrea Steffes
and Chef Riley Brown
are in charge
of filling up guests once again.
In and out grilled cheese,
table nine.
I have the Inside Out
Grilled Cheese.
It's so good. It's got this
crunchy cheese on the outside,
and on the inside, there's
guacamole and black beans.
It's very different than
any other grilled cheese
that you're going to find.
What are we making, Chef?
Salsa.
Anaheims,
roasted red bell pepper,
and roasted green pepper.
And jalapeños?
You've got it.
Whole stewed tomatoes.
Have the light on.
Green onions, little garlic,
toasted ground cumin.
-Beautiful.
-Little bit of sugar.
Thanks, honey.
-Chopped red onion.
-Agua?
That is actually white vinegar,
sriracha, cilantro,
and our house seasoning.
And that makes the salsa?
Now we're going to make
our black beans.
A little bit of olive oil.
Sweat the peppers
and onions.
Salsa.
Okay.
Canned beans, strained.
And a little bit
more of the magic dust?
Salt, garlic salt,
black pepper.
I'm going to swell up
like a puffer fish.
Then we just add
a little bit of water.
And how long are we going
to let these cook?
15 minutes. Basically just
bringing it to temperature.
-After this?
-We make the grilled cheese.
Little butter on the grill,
add our shredded cheese down.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
This is what makes it
inside out.
We're trying to get a crispy
and a chewy effect.
Cover that lid over there.
Let that steam so that
that cheese on top melts
while the cheese on bottom
crisps up just right.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Fresh-made guacamole on here.
Everybody tuning in
at home,
this is the weirdest
grilled cheese
we've ever seen on "Triple D."
Take a scoop of beans.
We'll hit it
with a little sriracha.
And that's all she wrote.
I don't know who's trying to be
funny-funny around here,
but that kind of looks
like somebody's hairline.
[ Laughs ]
[ Crunches ]
I've had a lot of crazy food,
dude, but this is taking it.
You get this fried crunch,
we called this the skirt.
One of first times
I ever saw this
was at the Squeeze Inn
in Sacramento.
And you love getting this
almost fried cheese.
Then you take delicious
beans and guacamole,
stick them inside of
a really thick quesadilla.
Dynamite.
Thank you.
Okay --
That's how I fist bump.
Get a kick out of it.
Things are getting weird.
All right, you guys,
I have those
Inside Out
Grilled Cheese for you.
It's just a really
unique flavor.
It's really good.
Really cheesy.
That's up there
in grilled cheese history.
-Exactly.
-Throwing the meat lover's up.
Their menu is very home-cooked.
Corn beef hash
and stuffed French toast.
I always try to save room
for a cinnamon roll.
Every part of it is perfect.
Two cinnamon rolls,
let's get these out.
It comes with a ton of icing.
It's huge.
It's like the size of my face.
It's amazing.
All right.
What's up next, Chef?
We're going to start the poolish
for our cinnamon rolls.
Yeast. Dry active?
Yep. Warm water.
And we add our flour.
Got it.
And this step we
actually mix by hand.
Okay.
This is going to set at room
temperature to rise
a little bit
for an hour and a half.
We're going to
start our dough.
Another round of yeast,
flour.
Water, eggs, oil,
salt, and sugar.
-And when's the poolish go in?
-Right now.
I've never seen it made
with a poolish.
You get a nice
finish with it.
Oh, it's a Finnish recipe.
Mm. Love Scandinavia.
We making a glaze?
Yes. A cream cheese frosting.
Powdered sugar, beat that,
half and half,
vanilla flavoring.
A little bit of salt.
We're on.
Okay. Next up?
Flour the surface area,
and we're going to
pull this guy out.
It's always fun
playing with dough.
You've got it going there,
buddy.
Then we're going to add
a little bit of butter
over the top of this.
You don't see handmade
cinnamon rolls much anymore.
-Doctor.
-Nurse?
Sugar, cinnamon,
and salt.
-Roll this up?
-Yes.
You're going to bake in that
tray with that parchment paper?
That's correct.
Dude, I want that one.
I think you made a wise
decision.
Look at that.
[ Whistles ]
Ah, someone's going to have
a little bit of a sugar problem
here in a second.
♪♪
Wow. There's some
great texture
in that cinnamon roll dough.
You're not shy
on cinnamon one bit.
The cream cheese frosting
has nice little tang to it.
Backs it up.
Nicely done.
Delicious.
You give me some knuckles.
Really good.
♪♪
Two cinnamon rolls, table five.
The cinnamon roll is this big.
It's like your grandma's
cinnamon roll,
but bigger and creamier.
I wish that the cinnamon roll
had some more frosting.
It's cutting corners here.
It's some of the greatest
food around.
All right, I got a Cuban down.
Everyone likes to come
to Herm's.
FIERI: [ Mouth full ] You have
a lot of enthusiasm about food.
You really take the time
to do what you're doing.
Well done.
♪♪
So, that's it
for this road trip,
but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
We're in, uh,
we're in Utah somewhere.
I don't know, but if I don't
make it home,
please call my family.
[ Laughter ]