You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know!
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was only
the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
In Boston...
If you want to come here,
you've got to
get ready to wait in line.
...the secret is out
at this Italian eatery...
We can't keep that
on the menu....
where the pasta and the portions
are pretty much perfect.
You are the real deal,
hands down the real deal.
Plus...
Oh. Oh.
...a Massachusetts diner
still killing the classics...
You got it going on,
girl.
...and a Baltimore hot spot...
Just turn me in 3 minutes.
Who needs to go
to the tanning bed?
...flipping the script
on one of my favorite foods.
This is not your average
pizza joint.
Beware.
Dude.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors,
this is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
All right, Hunter.
Back in 2010,
you were just 13 years old.
We shot this joint here
in Boston,
and I got to be
honest with you,
right after it aired,
everybody we knew said,
"Can you help me
get a reservation?"
There's just
so few tables.
The portions are awesome.
It's one of the best
Italian joints in town.
This is Rino's Place.
Oh, I love it.
♪♪
Pickup,
homemade cheese raviolis!
MAN: If you want the best
Italian food
in the city of Boston,
you come to Rino's.
All the pasta here
is homemade.
I come to Rino's so much,
I was here the last time
they were here for
"Triple D."
Everything that Tony makes
is out of this world.
This is the place to be.
FIERI: And she's not
the only one who thinks so.
Hi, there.
Since I met Big Tony DiCenso
in 2010,
this place has blown up!
It's been 150 times
that I've called you,
"Hey, listen,
I got a cousin in town.
Hey, listen I got a buddy
that's gonna be"...
Yeah,
and then we get them in.
Yeah, you always
get them in.
But I'm not kidding you,
if you want to come here,
you've got to get ready
to wait in line.
The tiniest little
busiest kitchen I've ever seen.
Pickup!
Homemade order --
Katie.
DICENSO: I do all the shopping
and everything.
I pick everything out myself,
my produce, everything.
Wait a minute.
Seriously?
Yes, sir.
Growing up in Italy,
we grew all our own vegetables,
raised all our own animals.
I raised my own animals,
too.
I named them
Hunter and Ryder.
[ Laughs ]
Now you've changed.
You wear a black jacket now.
You're like the Johnny Cash.
Everything else is good here?
You guys are still rocking
and rolling?
DICENSO: We're still rocking
and rolling.
The lobster ravs
are still made to order.
You know I love
the lobster rav.
We had that last time.
We're gonna boil
some lobsters.
10, 15 minutes here.
Okay.
Pick all the meat
out the tail and the claws.
This is for
the filling.
Yes.
All right. So we get all
the lobster meat out.
And the legs, also.
We're gonna roll
out the legs.
Yes.
His big hands and this.
Get after it, boss.
Squeeze all the meat
right out of it.
Look at that,
like lobster sausage.
That meat is super sweet
and super tasty,
a lot of work
for a little lobster.
Chop it up.
Do a little saute on it.
Go.
We're gonna make our filling,
fresh ricotta.
Parmesan Reggiano.
Parmesan Reggiano,
some parsley, salt,
pepper,
chilled lobster meat.
All right, brother.
Just fold it.
I like to leave it chunky.
Chunk of lobster.
There you go.
That's right.
So we got this ready.
Next thing is making
the pasta.
Add our eggs.
This is how my grandmother
taught me and my mother.
This is how we do it.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Because our pitchfork
is in the shop,
we're gonna whip
the eggs with this.
Each time he mixes
it around,
a little bit
more flour catches in.
Next thing is,
we'll start rolling this out.
We're gonna work our way
down to, like, 2 1/2.
Wow.
Look at this.
There should be music
to this right now.
This should be a video.
There you go.
Wow. You don't skimp
on the filling.
Nope.
I just want you
to see this.
That right there
is plenty,
but that is how much he puts
in a ravioli here. Crazy.
Right on top.
Press down until the two
pastas seal together.
And then you're off
to go.
We're gonna make the
lobster ravioli sauce now.
Fantastic.
Shallots, lobster meat.
Seriously?
Yep.
Salt.
Pepper.
Next, we'll add
our brandy.
Whoa!
Is that what happened?
Yeah. That's what happened.
That's what it is?
Yes.
That's what it is.
Just drop them
right in there.
Mmm.
There is nothing
I would change on that.
I've been to Italy.
I've had great pasta.
I got to tell you,
you're following
all the principles
but one.
What's that?
Ridiculous portion.
Oh, portion.
Let me show you.
Normal.
Normal, yes.
Tony.
I'm not kidding.
Easily 2 pounds of food.
Dude,
I'm beyond impressed.
Thank you.
Order up!
Look at that.
What is that? For a family?
No, that's just
a single portion.
That's a what?
Single portion.
That's one serving.
Yeah. We give you a handcart
to get you to your car.
What do you got?
Homemade cheese raviolis.
That's a big ravioli.
What?
That's how my grandmother
used to make them in Italy.
It's like a Frisbee.
Yeah.
Made to order.
Yes.
What's in here?
Ricotta cheese,
grated Romano cheese,
salt, pepper, parsley
in the ricotta filling.
Fresh-made pasta.
Yes, sir.
Mmm.
San Marzano
tomato sauce.
Garlic, San Marzano tomatoes,
salt,
pepper, water, Italian basil,
gives it a great, sweet flavor.
Let it cook down
for 10 minutes.
Let the sauce
and the raviolis incorporate,
a little bit
of Pecorino Romano now.
You get three of these
for an order.
Homemade cheese raviolis!
♪♪
Fresh is the key
right there.
Yeah.
Oh, my gosh.
That right there,
my brother...
Dude.
...delicious.
Thank you.
Simple, straight to the point,
great ingredients.
You outdo yourself
every time.
Thank you.
Cheese ravioli.
It's a light sauce. It doesn't
overpower the cheese ravioli.
The ricotta is so creamy.
It just melts in your mouth.
The red sauce is what makes it,
and they're so filling.
He makes them
the size of plates,
so you need help
walking out of here.
It's dangerous.
You sit down at that table...
Are you good?
...you think
you order one simple thing...
Chicken Parm.
...and by the time the dishes
come out, you're on the floor.
All right.
Enjoy.
What else you got for me?
Coming up...
Fire in the hole!
There we go.
...the hits just
keep coming...
This is
a steak-house-level chop.
...and coming.
I can't eat anymore.
All right.
I'm full unless you got
one more surprise.
Dig this.
I'm back in Boston with Hunter
checking in on an Italian spot
I hit back in 2010, and you know
when I go Italian...
It's got to be handmade.
It's got to be homemade.
It's got to be the real deal.
And big Tony over
at Rino's place, well,
he checked all the boxes.
Mmm. Mmm. Ah.
That's ridiculous.
You are the real deal.
If you haven't been here,
you're missing out.
I showed you 9 years ago.
Got to get here.
Since Guy came in,
people come from all over.
I'm sorry that the world found
out about our favorite place,
but you can't keep it
a secret too long.
FIERI: But the real secret
is knowing what to order.
All right.
What else you got for me?
Veal porterhouse
with roasted asparagus
and panzarotti,
which are potato croquettes
with goat cheese.
He says everything
with such authority.
♪♪
Season this with some salt
and pepper on both sides.
You hear that nice sear?
Now we're gonna place them
in the oven 2 to 3 minutes.
We're gonna make our
potato croquettes.
We're gonna add goat cheese
to our mashed potatoes,
salt, Italian parsley, grated
Romano cheese, black pepper.
Fold all the
ingredients together.
Form it like a football --
mini footballs.
Panko bread them, and then
we're gonna take them
right to the fryer.
This is our sauce --
porcini mushrooms,
brandy, shallots,
cream, veal demi-glace.
There we go.
Potato croquettes,
porcini mushroom sauce.
Veal porterhouse.
Pickup, please!
Just gorgeous,
cooked perfectly.
I mean, this is
a steakhouse-level chop.
Well, yes. We can't keep that
on the menu.
That's interesting.
I didn't know I was
cutting your food up
for you again.
I thought we stopped that,
like...
How many years ago?
Last year.
Yeah.
Look at that.
Could somebody eat
that entire thing?
Yeah.
The bone is clean.
The porcini mushrooms are
what make it, my brother.
Outstanding.
The veal is nice and tender
and a nice sweet sauce with it
and the croquettes,
dip in the sauce.
Unbelievable.
You know what?
I'm done.
I can't eat anymore.
All right.
I'm full unless you got
one more surprise.
Risotto.
Asparagus, Arborio rice,
add our fish stock,
salt and pepper,
a little bit of butter,
Romano cheese,
and then we top it
with pan-seared scallops.
♪♪
Look at that seared scallop.
Look at that crust on that.
Oh, my God.
Delicious, bud.
The food itself
is beyond amazing.
For me, this has been
like culinary Disneyland.
Let me tell you,
it's been a nice ride.
You keep crushing it, and you
are such a great representation
of what "Triple D"
is all about.
You're awesome.
Love you, brother.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Now coming up...
Doctor,
the patient is prepped.
...another must-see
in Massachusetts...
You're starring
in this show....
You just got to know
where to find it.
Somerville.
Cambridge.
And shake them.
And jazz hands.
Jazz hands.
So back in 2014,
I found this funky joint taking
classic bar staples up a notch.
Well, I'm just not exactly
quite sure where.
I'm in Cambridge, Massachusetts,
or Somerville.
I'm right on the line.
Now it's getting even more
confusing
because they've got new places
all over the state.
This is Trina's Starlite Lounge.
♪♪
When "Triple D" and Guy came
to Trina's, everybody loved it.
You're starring
in this show.
That's true.
That's a big deal.
MAN: I mean, it may seem
like a dive bar,
but they really care about
the quality of the food.
Hash down for haddock.
It's really innovative but also
comfortable and familiar.
FIERI: That's because chef
and owner Suzi Maitland
brings her Southern charm
to just about any town she's in.
Somerville.
And do the other.
Cambridge.
And shake them.
And jazz hands.
Jazz hands.
We had such a blast
filming this.
Oh.
Oh, yeah, no, hands.
He really makes you feel
comfortable.
We'll be making our fried
chicken and buttermilk waffles.
Okay, and we'll work
with the whole bird,
or are you
breaking the bird down?
Breaking the whole bird
down.
Break it down
like hammer time?
Oh, oh.
[ Laughs ]
There you go.
[ Both laugh ]
We're gonna do buttermilk
first, paprika,
a little bit of garlic,
dried marjoram, nice floral.
How long is this
gonna marinate?
Overnight. We're gonna go ahead
and make the chicken dredge.
Let's get after this.
Flour, paprika,
dried marjoram, dried thyme,
tarragon, mustard.
Loading it up.
Cayenne,
baking powder, and salt.
We're gonna dredge it
and let it set.
And then we're gonna throw it
right in the fryer.
350, cook it off
until brown.
What temp in the oven?
350, as well.
Now we'll be making
the waffle.
♪♪
[ Both laugh ]
It is ready.
A little bit of salt, chive,
and then hot pepper syrup.
♪♪
That's good fried chicken
like your mom would make.
Mmm!
You got it going on, girl.
Fried chicken
and waffles up!
Suzi brings a lot
of creative flavor
to whatever she
puts her mind to, really.
The fried chicken
is really good.
Their mac and cheese is classic.
The Starlite burger
is so delicious.
MAITLAND: The Starlite burger
has been on the menu
since day one, and it starts
with our wing sauce.
So we're gonna start with
a little bit of oil,
add in jalapeños, red bell
peppers, poblanos, and garlic,
and then we're gonna add
some chili flake and salt,
red wine vinegar,
simple syrup, and our honey,
and that's what makes
this all sticky and sweet.
After it simmers for 45 minutes,
we're gonna blend it up
and let it cool
and mix it with our house-made
mayo and Dijon mustard.
Now we're ready to cook off
our burgers.
First, it's just a little salt
and pepper
and then a hot, hot griddle.
We use white American cheese.
It melts really well,
and it has great flavor.
Drop the fries.
That's gonna be our base
for this burger,
and here is some coleslaw.
We're gonna top it with these
two patties and finish with that
Starlite sauce, and here
we have the Starlite burger.
It's awesome.
It's, like, big and juicy.
They got, like, tons of cheese.
You got the french fries
on there.
They add, like,
a nice crunch to it.
This burger is kind of a big,
delicious mess,
and it works perfectly well
with the tots.
Russets?
Yep, Idaho.
So we're just gonna
shred them.
And then we're just gonna put
it into water to rinse it off.
Squeeze all that
water out.
Then we're gonna take
cornstarch,
and we're really gonna
coat the potatoes.
Doctor, the patient
is prepped.
There we go.
And then we're just gonna
sprinkle potatoes
on a sheet pan,
put this in the oven
for about 20 minutes.
Let's see the rest of it,
girl.
Spanish onions, salt,
garlic powder, chives.
We just mix it all together
with our hands and then ball it.
Now, take them
in the fryer, 350?
350.
Bring me the tots.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Well, I got good news,
and I got bad news.
What do you want
first?
Bad news.
These are for me.
Good news is,
they're really good.
Really?
Awesome.
After "Triple D,"
we started to expand.
There is Audubon
in the Fenway area.
Paddle Inn up in Newburyport,
Massachusetts
and Trina's Starlite Lounge
in Amesbury, Massachusetts.
Suzi crushes it.
She can do this
wherever she goes.
The menu changes enough
to keep it interesting for me.
Blue-plate specials
are always changing every day.
People love the specials.
Today's is gonna be
a seafood bake.
We have our local haddock,
shrimp, and scallops.
First, we're gonna season our
seafood with salt and pepper.
We'll take some oil, throw in
our haddock, scallops, shrimp.
We're gonna go ahead and let
this get a real nice sear on it,
and then we're gonna start
with our vegetables, garlic,
leeks, corn, tomatoes,
and then we're gonna hit it
with our sherry cream,
use a little bit of sherry,
give it more flavor.
I'm gonna put the cream
into the seafood.
We're gonna top
with garlicky, buttery
bread crumbs,
throw it in the Salamander,
and we're just gonna finish
with a little bit of a scallion
and give it
a little bit more flavor.
The seafood bake.
The seafood is really fresh
which makes it light,
but then she adds bread crumb
and lots of butter
and makes it much
more comforting.
It is absolutely incredible.
It does have a broth,
but you can take a spoon to it,
a fork to it.
It's really delicious.
The road to Flavortown is paved
with Suzi's blue-plate specials.
You're really nice.
You've got a big personality
in food,
and you do things right.
Awesome.
Thank you.
Nice job, Chef.
Some high quality.
[ Laughs ]
Right there is what we like
to call the whole package.
Now, coming up in Baltimore,
a pizza place serving up
out-of-the-box pies...
Oh, oh, oh, what are
you doing?
...that can fit...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now what are you
doing?
...in a box.
Dude. I'll give you
the high-five now.
Oh, man!
♪♪
Back in 2011, I went
to this place in Baltimore
that was twisting up
traditional pie.
Now, these days, they've got
a new, bigger spot,
and just like the name says,
it's still all about the square.
This is Joe Squared pizza.
♪♪
Chicken avocado.
It's great pizza.
It's just a great atmosphere.
You really can't go wrong.
He made his mark
down the street,
and people have followed him
to this spot.
FIERI: That would be the pied
piper himself,
owner Joe Edwardsen,
who's luring folks in
with his smoking-hot pies.
You go coal-fired because
it can burn hotter.
800 to 900 degrees
on the floor,
1,500 to 2,000
topping off the dough.
Holy schnike, dude!
That is the hottest oven
I've ever been by!
EDWARDSEN: This is
the hottest food oven
in the state of Maryland,
straight coal.
Just turn me
in 3 minutes.
Who needs to go
to the tanning bed?
That's crazy.
The whole pizza is designed
to be cooked in that oven,
fast cooked, retain a good
amount of moisture in the crust
but with a good amount of char.
First, we're gonna add
in some flour and your water,
and you're just mixing
it up.
I'm just trying to get the yeast
to spread.
Building a bigger starter.
Exactly.
Hi, man.
That's...
Yeah, buddy.
Just kidding.
Oh, dude,
not supposed to leave
somebody hanging.
Pour it in the machine,
and we're just putting equal
parts of flour and water.
It'll start rising back up, you
know, getting nice and spongy.
Now you add another 2/3
of flour.
One cup of salt.
Okay.
We get her started.
Then we add the oil.
You let that proof.
About 2 hours or so.
Man, what a labor of love
this is.
♪♪
Grab your chunk
of dough.
Oh, oh, oh,
what are you doing?
You're sheeting this?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, there's two principles --
throwing it by hand
or running it
through a sheeter.
All right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Now what are you doing?
Now we're cutting it.
I've been sitting here
waiting to see,
how are you gonna pull the
dough, make it perfectly round,
but it's not even
a round form.
No.
I'm down with it.
We also serve them on these
screens,
so we cook it so hot,
there's so much moisture
trapped in the dough, if I put
it on a plate, it sogs up quick.
It's gonna steam right out.
This is going for what pizza?
Bacon and clam is the one
we'll be cooking today.
[ Inhales sharply ]
My middle name
is bacon and clam.
Topped down with roasted garlic,
whole garlic cloves
that I sauteed in oil.
Salt, pepper, Romano,
Parm,
a couple cups of cream,
and some oil.
Ready to go.
I'll go thin on it
because it's strong.
Okay.
Frozen clam.
Chop the bacon down.
Bocconcini.
That's a ciliegine.
Ciliegine
is cherry-sized.
Sliced Vidalia onion.
Asiago.
You grate
all your cheeses?
Uh-huh.
How long we going
down for?
For about a minute.
You guys would not believe
how hot it is standing
6 feet away
from this thing.
Nice.
♪♪
Look at that.
I love the screen idea.
Mmm.
Wow.
Crust is cooked off
perfect.
Mmm.
Nice texture.
Nice chew.
This is a lot of clams,
great garlic sauce.
Dude, I'll give you
the high-five now.
Oh, man.
Nicely done.
Money.
FIERI: And he's also cashing in
on another pie
featuring that
same garlic sauce.
EDWARDSEN:
Cumin-braised lamb pizza.
We start with two lamb
shoulders, coriander, cumin,
about four sticks of cinnamon,
saffron, carrots and celery,
ginger, jalapeños,
Vidalia onions and garlic,
crushed tomato.
Mix it up a bit.
This will cook 2 1/2 to 3 hours.
Now some roasted garlic sauce,
fresh mozzarella.
Here is the lamb
we just roasted.
Now a little roasted eggplant.
Vidalia onions and then
just the Romano cheese,
and that's it, ready to go in
the oven about 40 seconds or so.
We put a little mint
and parsley over top.
There you go,
the cumin lamb pizza.
WOMAN: Great flavors
including the mint
gives it a little sharpness.
The lamb is very tender,
falls apart really easily.
WOMAN:
The crust is fantastic.
It melts in your mouth
with the rest of it.
It's a perfect blend.
EDWARDSEN:
Last time Guy came here,
we were one block away
at a different location.
This is a much nicer location.
You can't see,
but there's air conditioning.
The things that made it great
in the old space...
Pizza joint,
lot of live music,
a cool bar.
...still
make it great here.
WOMAN: Joe is a wonderful,
wonderful mad scientist.
He kind of hits
all the spots.
We can get a nice range
of pizzas --
shrimp andouille pizza,
chicken avocado pizza.
EDWARDSEN:
We start with avocado sauce.
Next is our mozzarella
and provolone,
black beans,
white corn, stewed chicken,
pickled red onions
and the cheddar.
Now ready to go in the oven.
That'll be about 40 seconds.
We're done.
We finish with cilantro
and a wedge of lime.
Chicken avocado ready
for pickup!
MAN: I like it because it's
a little bit spicy,
really tasty,
and actually pretty light.
♪♪
Joe Squared pizza joint,
you're amazing.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you.
This is not your average
pizza joint.
Beware.
Mmm.
Dude.
Joe's spin on the old standards
is definitely something
to see and taste,
and he's not the only one making
waves with his inventive eats
because Suzi
at Trina's Starlite Lounge
is charming her customers with
her next-level diner classics,
and Tony at Rino's is still
bringing down the house
with his homemade pasta
and huge portions
plus all the other
"Triple D" joints killing it
with their own creations,
and we'll see those next time
on "Triple D Nation."
Watch your face.
Oldie but a goody.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
Bianca?
What was that?
Bianca's a dancer.
[ Laughs ]