People are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because Triple D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip, a place
pitching major league burgers.
Go big or go home.
Or come here and go home big.
And spreading the love
all over Massachusetts.
Give me a hug.
All right.
That's what I'm talking about.
Plus an Italian joint in Boston,
not skipping on the portions.
Because there's nothing left
in the ocean now?
Or the palate.
Awesome. Primo.
And it's a "Triple D" first.
The sirens are going off,
the flood of Flavortown.
Where a ramen spot in El Paso
becomes an overnight sensation.
The last meal I had last night,
the first meal I had today.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D" Nation.
♪♪
On "Triple D" Nation, it's not
about a bunch of firsts.
Most of the places we're
visiting I've been to before.
Going back there to see
how things are going,
but today, well,
I've got a first for you.
I'm here in El Paso, Texas,
and just last night
I was having some
fantastic ramen with my buddies,
and I got done eating.
I said, you know what?
We've got to feature this on
"Triple D" Nation.
This is Kaedama.
♪♪
Bowl in, order up.
These two gentlemen were
the first ones
to actually
introduce ramen to our city.
They hit a home run.
It's just
absolutely delicious.
You can taste the care
that they take
putting
this bowl together.
FIERI: That's dude-up
ramen ringleaders
Andres Romero
and Gabe Valencia,
good buddies of mine for --
let's see, over 12 hours.
I come to El Paso,
I get done shooting "Triple D."
Everybody's hungry.
We wanted a place to eat.
Want some ramen.
We tracked down
this funky little spot.
Mind you, this is
all last night.
You know, I was talking
to you last night.
Right.
So let's go
from the beginning.
Are people of El Paso,
are they tuned in
to what great ramen is?
Valencia: Most in El Paso had no
idea what it was,
so it had to be good.
We're the ones
that introduced them to it.
-You got to set the bar high.
-Yeah.
I had the dipping ramen.
Yeah, that's called
a tsukemen.
Instead of the noodles
sitting inside of a broth.
The broth
is on the side.
And it is a dish
I hadn't had before.
It's concentrated broth.
It's thicker, a little saltier.
You dip your noodles in there
and then eat them.
FIERI: But the crown jewel
of this place is the tonkotsu.
The tonkotsu,
that's the house bowl.
VALENCIA:
That's our flagship.
Tonkotsu, no egg.
What are we using
to build the stock,
the base
of this great ramen?
VALENCIA:
Pork feet and water.
-Pig's feet and water.
And it's going to boil
for 12 hours.
That's a lot of pig's feet.
We're heads and feet
above the rest.
Now we're going to make the...
which is the seasoning.
The...
sets kind of the tone
for what the flavor of the bowl
is gonna be.
Yeah. This is all the
personality of each bowl.
Minced garlic.
-Okay.
Dashi, It's as smoked bonito
flake powder, minced ginger.
Salt.
We're a good team.
I'm going to start work here
on my off weeks.
-Sugar.
-That's it.
That's the batter
right there.
-So the noodles.
-Sun noodles.
Sun noodles out of Hawaii.
That's the Cadillac of noodles.
All right,
so we dropped the noodles.
Cook them
for about two minutes.
To me, this is one of
the most important factors.
You have to have the ability
to drain that water off,
and you have a backup
going at the same time.
Once one of the baskets
gets a little too starchy,
we switch over
to the other one.
Flush the water, cycle it.
We're good to go.
Smart man. Super smart.
And then we build a bowl
from the noodle.
-Right.
-So the...goes in first.
These noodles in here later.
Ladle this broth.
Look at the color of that broth
just from cooking down
those pork feet.
Love it.
Mix that into the broth.
Scallions.
The sirens are going off
with flood in Flavortown.
-Narutomakis.
-Pork belly.
Blackened garlic oil.
Right there, it's ready to go.
Where do you go?
I go broth. I just want to see
what the broth is like.
♪♪
It's creamy. It's rich.
It coats your mouth, your salt's
right, your seasoning's right.
That's a pretty
broad spectrum of flavors.
♪♪
I ate that ramen bowl.
I am "good night."
Last meal I had last night,
the first meal I had today.
SERVER:
Here's your tonkotsu.
The flavor pops.
Saltiness, not too spicy.
The pork belly is delicious.
It breaks apart on your tongue
as soon as you eat it.
So fresh.
The meat was tender,
complemented the noodles
very well.
WOMAN:
What I love about this place
is that you finish the bowl,
you get another one.
You can order Kaedama.
Once your noodles are done,
get a whole other batch
of noodles in there.
It's like two bowls in one.
How many different types
of ramen are we doing, Gabe?
We offer six bowls.
There's a couple of bowls
that have an El Paso flair
to them.
The chipotle one.
We decided to incorporate
a little bit of spice
into our bowl.
We're going to start off
with making the seasoning mix --
onion powder, garlic powder,
ginger powder,
smoked paprika,
and some salt.
Sprinkle it
on our chicken breasts
and stick it in the oven.
We're going to make our...
which is our seasoning
for the bowl.
Salts, sugar, smoked paprika,
fire-roasted tomatoes,
whole garlic cloves,
miso paste, a little bit
of water, some onions.
And last is
the star of the show,
the chipotle pepper
and adobo sauce.
We're just going to go ahead
and blend it up,
and right there
it's ready to go.
So this is the chicken
we just roasted,
ready to brown on our flattop.
So now we're ready to assemble
our chipotle bowl.
We're going to put our...
noodles,
gonna pour a little bit
of veggie broth in there,
scallions, sweet corn,
fire roasted diced tomatoes,
chicken,
one of our marinated eggs,
sesame seeds, chile threads.
Chipotle, order up.
The chipotle bowl
is my favorite.
Spices are balanced out.
It's like a tomato-y chipotle
kind of broth. It's delicious.
It's not too spicy,
it's not overwhelming.
The chicken is real tender.
It's good flavor.
♪♪
Never has it happened like this.
I was just here for dinner.
I mean, I went from here
to my hotel back here.
I was so inspired,
because if we ever talk
about what it takes to make it
in the restaurant business,
you two are
a shining example of that.
That's blood,
sweat and tears, guys,
and here's
your graduation present.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
-You never know baby, right?
-Appreciate it.
Smart guys.
FIERI: Now, coming up...
It's not Flavortown.
It's "Flava-town."
FIERI:
A Boston burger joint hitting
home runs all over this state.
Wicked good, wicked killer,
wicked awesome.
FIERI:
When I hit up a burger joint,
I'm looking
for something special,
something out of the box,
and this place in Boston
did not disappoint.
Table three,
Killer Bee.
These days, they're rocking
four locations, a food truck,
and a burger named
for one of Beantown's
biggest baseball legends.
This is
the Boston Burger Company.
♪♪
Table five, Sophie.
WOMAN:
I saw this place on "Triple D,"
so I had to come and check it
out, and it's fantastic.
If you want the best burger
in Boston,
you definitely got to come
to Boston Burger.
All the burgers here at
Boston Burger are really unique.
It's one of the things that can
keep you coming back for years.
FIERI: And we're back, too,
thanks to owner Paul Malvone,
who I met back in 2012.
But that wasn't his first time
in the spotlight.
My girl Rachael Ray, she gave
you props about your burgers.
Yes.
Before "Triple D" came in, we
were on the "Rachael Ray Show."
It was a competition
we happened to win.
I got a hug on the show.
A hug? Really?
Don't think you're
getting that from me.
[ Laughs ]
You will.
So what are we making?
What kind of burger
are you making me?
We're making the Mac Attack.
That's just what I need.
We're gonna make some
mac and cheese, gonna
make the cheese sauce.
Take our chopped onions,
the butter.
We're gonna
let that sweat up.
Throw the flour
right in.
So we've got the roux built,
cooked out the flour.
Got the onions in there.
Now we're gonna
go with some milk?
Gonna go with some milk.
Cheeses.
American,
some cheddar.
Cheddar,
wicked cheddar.
Wicked good, wicked killer,
wicked awesome.
You have the accent.
It's not Flavortown.
It's "Flava-town."
[ Laughs ]
Now we're doing some
shredded cheddar-Jack cheese.
So stir it up.
Get it done.
Boil some water, make some
pasta, and there we go?
Absolutely.
Alright.
Cheese sauce is made.
Hot sauce.
♪♪
New ingredient
I'm adding
to my mac and cheese
flavor profiles -- hot sauce.
Where's that been
all my life?
Andale, mi amigo.
Gonna throw some Parmesan,
little Pecorino Romano,
and we're gonna throw in
some salt and pepper.
I'm just gonna mix
this right up.
Now you dump it in the pan,
let it set up overnight?
Absolutely. If it's too hot,
it's gonna fall apart.
Too hot, it'll fall apart.
Okay.
We'll throw a burger right down.
Okay, nice 80/20.
Throw on some bacon.
Throw that right on the grill.
Put some
cheddar-Jack cheese on.
♪♪
I'm gonna get, like, one of
those road construction signs
on my heart.
Look at this.
Mac Attack.
♪♪
Mmm!
Really good meat
in the burger.
♪♪
Good chew, good texture,
good fat.
I understand why Rachael
gave you a hug.
[ Laughs ]
I'm still
not getting one?
We'll talk about it.
Alright.
Mac Attack,
when we first started,
we'd sell, you know,
maybe 10, 15 a day or so,
but now we sell thousands
of Mac Attack burgers a month.
If you're gonna go
for a big burger,
putting mac and cheese
on it's pretty gangster.
Go big or go home.
Or come here
and go home big.
It's their new slogan.
FIERI: And he took that slogan
and ran with it.
Before "Triple D" came in,
we had a 28-seat restaurant.
After the show aired, we
doubled our seating capacity,
four restaurants now,
a food truck.
FIERI: Plus, he added
a couple new all-stars.
MALVONE:
A Big Papi Burger.
We collaborated
with David Ortiz,
so the proceeds goes
towards his charity.
So we're gonna be making
our homemade guacamole.
First, we're gonna
mash up our avocados.
We're gonna add tomatoes,
chopped red onion,
pickled jalapeño.
Got to have
a little heat in there.
Fresh-cut cilantro,
black pepper,
salt, and some lime juice.
And we're gonna
mix that all together.
We're good with the guacamole.
We're all set and ready to go.
That is certified Angus beef.
We'll add the bacon
and the hot dog to the grill.
It's all gonna go
on top of the burger.
Once it's all cooked,
at the very end,
we're gonna fry our egg.
Complete our burger --
lettuce, two slices of tomato,
little sprinkle of black pepper.
We're gonna plate the burger
on top of that,
guacamole, house-made
pickled red onions, fried egg,
that Papi sauce,
which is ketchup,
a lot of sugar, paprika,
sriracha, white wine vinegar.
Then just a little bit of water.
Turn up the heat.
Mix that all together.
Mix that in
with some mayonnaise,
and it's a sweet, tangy,
creamy deliciousness.
The Big Papi.
Big Papi's a big name here.
That's why they have
a big burger named after him.
A filling, flavorful,
just an amazing burger.
MAN: It's huge, and the sauce
is really, really tasty
and totally unique.
I've eaten here many,
many, many a times,
and every single burger
is very, very good.
The Big Papi's excellent.
The big mac burger is very good.
The Sophie burger's
phenomenal, as well.
The Sophie burger is one of
our most popular burgers now.
Sophie is actually
a real person.
She's a tour guide in Italy.
So we're gonna make
our lemon vinaigrette.
We're gonna add
a little olive oil, lemon juice,
honey, some Dijon mustard,
salt, pepper, white vinegar.
And we're just gonna
whisk that up.
We're gonna take our burger,
give it a flip.
Top that with some prosciutto
and goat cheese.
It's not gonna melt.
It's gonna get a little soft.
We're gonna add our salad,
the house-made
lemon vinaigrette.
Burger right on top.
Crushed candied walnuts,
balsamic glaze, fig jam.
And there it is --
a little bit salty, very sweet,
and just a little nuts,
like Sophie is.
WOMAN: Sophie burger
has that perfect taste
of sweet and tangy
at the same time
because of the goat cheese.
WOMAN #2:
You have the prosciutto
and you have to fig jam
with the vinaigrette.
It balances everything out
very nicely.
You totally recommend it
to anybody that's a burger fan.
Highly recommend.
It's wicked awesome.
Give me a hug.
Alright.
That's what I'm talking about.
There you go. See?
[ Laughs ]
Sophie's got a burger.
Big Papi has a burger.
And I'm assuming
at some point in time,
"Triple D" burger
is in the works.
Am I right, Paul?
Alright, coming up,
we're staying in Boston...
You smell the garlic.
You smell --
I'm saying it like him.
...where these Italian dudes
are cooking up classics
that you just can't
get enough of.
My flavor jets
have just turned on.
Boston is one of those cities
known for their
melting pot of flavors.
You've got Korean, Vietnamese,
Colombian, Pakistani.
I mean, you name it.
Back in 2012,
I just couldn't help myself.
I had to go check out
everybody's go-to favorite,
that tried and true Italian.
Sausage cacc and ziti.
And they're still kicking out
some killer dishes.
This is
Italian Express Pizzeria.
Don't be skimpy.
Let's go.
Tastes just like my grandmother
used to make.
I think Guy picked a great spot
for his show.
I agree with that.
I've heard that I look like Guy.
I've know Jimmy and Jon
for almost 50 years.
They've got a golden heart
and a golden touch
in the kitchen, that's for sure.
FIERI: That would be
long-time buddies
Jimmy Iannuzzi
and Jonathan Harker.
What does Jonathan
do here?
Jonathan looks great,
takes care of himself,
and I work
a million hours a week.
Really?
Yeah.
That's nice, Jonathan.
People can't forget
these two faces.
Or the Italian dishes
they're cranking out.
Where'd you learn to cook?
My grandmother.
Dig it.
Yep. Nonni.
When we were on "Triple D,"
we made our homemade fettuccine
with our frutti di mare.
Frutti di mare,
here it is.
Now we're gonna make
my famous pasta sauce, marinara.
Famous?
Famous.
Okay.
Everything here's famous.
Everything's world-famous.
You know, we said
it was back then,
but now it really is.
Fresh chopped onions.
Chopped garlic.
Starting to smell good?
Fantastic.
Take our sauce,
just dump this in here.
While he's doing this, my flavor
jets have just turned on.
There's something
about tomato sauce.
You smell the garlic.
You smell --
I'm saying it like him.
Salt, pepper,
fresh chopped basil.
Stir it up.
And just let it go
low and slow.
About three hours.
Magic's gonna happen.
We're gonna
steam our clams.
So we have our mussels
and our littlenecks.
Some white wine.
Turn the heat on.
Little chicken stock.
Mussels.
Alright, there we go.
And the littleneck clams.
And a little cover.
That's it.
We're gonna start
our sauce.
Butter,
fresh chopped garlic,
some white wine,
some chicken stock.
I want to take
our delicious marinara.
♪♪
Alright,
gonna take some salt,
fresh chopped onion,
some crushed red pepper.
We're gonna cover it.
These are done.
Okay.
Gonna strain the juice.
Look at that.
Alright.
I'm gonna take my shrimp,
calamari.
Let's just let that cook
for a couple seconds.
Now the handmade
semolina fettuccine.
That's right.
Salted water.
All of it?
Yeah.
Then it's gonna be
enough for 18 people.
Ridiculous.
This is one of the most
popular dishes here.
'Cause there's nothing left
in the ocean now?
That's --
♪♪
Mmm! Seafood's
cooked perfectly.
Pasta's got nice bite
to it.
I'm impressed.
Awesome.
FIERI: But they're not
just pulling from the sea.
We're gonna be making
veal saltimbocca
with the homemade fettuccine.
Take our veal
and we're gonna pound it.
You don't want
to pound them too thin
because they'll cook real fast.
And, you know, you got
to have a veal guy.
I had a fish guy.
I still do.
You got to have a fish guy.
Yeah, no, listen.
I say it all the time.
You got to have a great butcher.
You got to have
a great hairstylist.
Right.
A good bail bondsman
and an incredible fishmonger.
You got to
have a fish guy.
But you got to have a veal guy.
We're gonna take this
and just dredge them
in white unbleached flour,
and we're gonna put it
in the pan with some olive oil
and we're gonna cook it
till it's nice and golden brown.
Now we're gonna make
our saltimbocca sauce.
Butter.
I got a butter guy, too.
I'm only kidding.
Marsala wine.
This gives all the flavor.
Fresh mushrooms.
Add our veal.
Parma prosciutto.
Place these on the veal.
Mozzarella cheese.
Melt that all on top.
Slide the veal on top
of my homemade fettuccine.
Fresh parsley.
Veal saltimbocca,
homemade fettuccine.
MAN:
The veal is so tender.
Ham and the cheese
over a bed of fresh fettuccine.
And it's just to die for.
Unbelievable.
It's the freshest veal.
It's phenomenal.
And the portion's always huge.
It's ridiculous.
It's delicious.
Fresh as can be.
It's fun.
You know what?
When you say fun, you exude fun.
"It's fun."
[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: And coming up...
You're gonna
have so much fun.
Eating this fish.
...the fun just doesn't stop,
with more pasta, Parm...
So tell me about
good eggplant Parm.
...and personality.
What are you looking at?
FIERI:
We're in Boston touching base
with a joint I came across
in 2012.
FIERI: There's a lot of Italian
restaurants in Boston.
Lord knows I've eaten
at half of them.
How do you
describe yourself?
No thrills, home-cooked,
family-type neighborhood joint.
And they're whipping up
the dishes to prove it.
This will also involve
some type of me
sleeping in the Camaro
down the street at a park,
just like usual.
Haddock Margarita.
We made a dish with Guy
called the Haddock Margarita.
You know, we said it was fun.
You're gonna have
so much fun.
Eating this fish.
Yeah.
What are you looking at?
Your grandma made
margarita haddock?
Nonni used to make this
when we were kids.
Let's go.
So we got a fillet of haddock.
Beautiful fillet.
Fun time.
[ Party horn blows ]
Dredge the fish
in the flour.
Season?
Nope, just plain
white flour.
Olive oil in the pan.
Okay.
Let that get
a little warm.
Then we're gonna take the fish
and cover it in the egg.
Put this right
in the hot oil.
While this is cooking up here,
we're gonna start our sauce.
Okay.
First we're gonna
take our butter,
pinch of salt,
pinch of black pepper.
This fish is fun. Fun fish.
I'm having a ball.
White wine,
chicken stock.
Okay.
Gonna take some lemon,
a squeeze of lemon in here.
♪♪
Look at that?
That perfect?
Right in this sauce.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Here we go.
I'm just gonna cover this
for a couple minutes.
Take the fish.
Wow, it's just about
ready to fall apart.
Yeah.
Whoa!
You can do it.
Almost.
Go, go, go, go.
There was one little mistake.
I wouldn't call it a mistake.
Ooh.
Is that a problem?
The Russian judge
gives him an 8.
Oh, there you go.
And this is how your grandma
would make it?
That's it.
This how Nonni would do it.
Awesome. Primo.
Simple, pure,
super fresh.
Thank you.
I was pretty proud
to have Guy sit there
and eat the whole thing.
You know,
that's quite a compliment.
FIERI: But I'm not the only
recognizable face at this joint.
♪♪
We had Mayor Menino.
He was part of our episode.
So tell me about
good eggplant Parm.
Well, it's good cheese,
good sauce,
and nice and tender
eggplant.
This is the best.
These guys do it right.
They do it right.
That was quite an honor,
then to have our new mayor,
Marty Walsh, come was another
great honor for us.
Chicken Parm ravioli,
Mr. Mayor.
The chicken Parm's amazing.
Ravioli's great.
♪♪
White meat, free-range chicken.
Pound it out,
dredge it in flour,
egg wash, plain bread crumbs.
Panfry these.
Nonni's marinara sauce,
mozzarella cheese.
Put it in our pizza oven and
let it cook for a few minutes.
Ravioli, put them in a hot,
salted water.
And then we're gonna plate them.
Chicken Parm ravioli.
Chicken Parm's crispy on the
outside, tender on the inside.
Nice mozzarella.
Sauce just accents it.
It's just a great meal.
Melts in your mouth.
Oh, 1,000% I'm taking it home.
[ Chuckles ]
Since Guy was here,
the place has kind of exploded.
It literally happened
overnight.
We want to just keep
a good thing going,
keep making people happy
with our one location.
Yeah, we can't be
two places at once.
We want to be here.
So what we decided was we would
just really expand our patio
to be able to
accommodate more people.
Another benefit,
we've been able to catch up
on a lot of our bills.
Look at that, huh?
I got a Lamborghini.
I got a Ferrari.
We have two red Vespas.
I got a Bentley.
I don't have
any of that stuff.
You guys
are awesome, man.
-I get it.
-Thank you guys.
I'm a fan.
When you've got multiple mayors
busting down your door,
you know you hit the big time.
And so do the fellas at Kaedama,
who introduced ramen
to the residents of El Paso,
and Paul
at Boston Burger Company,
who's naming burgers
after big shots
and taking over the town.
Plus there are plenty
of other places
knocking them out of the park,
and we'll check them out
next time on "Triple D Nation."
[ Laughs ]
Show me what Sammy looks like
when he dances.
Oh, he's like...
That's how Sammy dances.
Really?
Swear to God, just like that.
I wouldn't call that dancing.
I'd call that having a tic.
Yeah, your boy's moving around.
Yeah, there's something
going on.
[ Laughs ]