Man, it sure is nice to have
the Camaro home.
It's never here.
Exactly. And since
we're on quarantine...
Yeah,
the car's on quarantine.
...the car's on quarantine,
also.
And we've been doing
some great cooking here
at the Fieri house, but...
I just want to go out.
I just want to go out to eat.
We can't go out to eat.
But we can get
some great takeout.
I think I've got some
Triple-D restaurants
that would love
to send us some takeout.
This is "Triple-D: Takeout."
Hunter, you missed a spot.
No. Come on.
♪♪
All right, Ryder,
it's left up to you and me.
You see, Hunter,
I don't know where he's at.
But the deal is,
I've got these chefs
that have sent us
some outrageous food.
Let's see.
Niko and Sikey from Seattle.
They sent French dips.
There's not a thing going on
that isn't 100%.
Then Benny Lin sends us
shrimp from Alaska.
That's what I'm talking about!
Then we've got Luigi.
You know -- Luigi's pizza
from San Diego.
RYDER: Yeah.
He's not sending pizza.
He's sending arancini.
Delicious, Luigi. This is how
you do arancini, man.
And then Jay from
Mike's City Diner in Boston,
he's sending us kebabs.
Lights-out dish, bro.
You hungry?
Yep.
All right. You run the cameras.
I got the show.
All right,
my brothers and sisters.
welcome to "Triple-D: Takeout"
with four of my favorite chefs
from "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
Everybody feeling good?
-Fantastic.
-Feeling good.
The "Triple-D" OGs.
Let me see. Who has got
the most tenure out of you?
I think it's Voula's -- Niko,
Sikey, and Voula herself.
We got Benny Lin all the way
out of North Pole, Alaska.
By the way, Benny,
I love that the Pagoda sign
is right behind you.
Right.
We got the one and only Luigi
from Pizzeria Luigi.
We got our buddy Jay Hajj over
in Boston for Mike's City Diner.
I got Ryder over here
working the camera.
Typically, I have
my right-hand man, Hunter,
but I think he's taking
care of the goats.
We're here
in the outdoor kitchen.
I'm wearing this shirt,
rerf.us,
which is
Restaurant Employee Relief Fund.
People can go to this website
and make a donation to all
the employees that have lost
their job due to the pandemic.
And if you're an employee
that's lost your job,
it's a place to go and sign up
to get the opportunity
for a $500 grant.
So, here's the game plan.
I asked you to send me a dish
that you're super-proud of,
and then I'll do the final steps
of the preparation
so I can taste it
in its best form.
Who wants to go first?
Luigi, San Diego.
What year were you
for "Triple-D"?
October 2008.
Look at that bad boy.
Mmm.
This is really great pizza.
That's ridiculous.
I'm moving in your house.
What's going on
in the pizza world?
The restaurants are
all closed, and we decided
to self-quarantine
all the employees and everybody.
We're planning on reopening
at the beginning of May.
I don't know what you sent me.
I am a little bit scared.
♪♪
Oh, you got both. Okay.
I don't need both?
The first package was
extra stuff that I sent in case
the rice
wasn't good to be used.
This packaging's recyclable?
Yep.
Oh, I got
to keep this stuff.
This is awesome.
What are we making -- arancini?
Yes, correct.
Now, arancini is one
of those famous Italian dishes
that everybody loves.
Is it something
that everybody eats in Italy
on a regular basis?
It's very popular in Sicily.
People eat it on the streets
kind of like you would
a slice of pizza
in New York.
Give me
the rundown here, buddy.
You get some rice.
So, you cook
the Arborio rice.
It's already mixed
with some butter,
Parmesan cheese,
and Pecorino cheese.
Okay.
What do we do first?
Warm up the sauce.
Then add the peas in it.
What's in the meat sauce,
Luigi?
Tenderloin beef.
Beef tenderloin?
Yeah.
That's not beef tenderloin,
Luigi.
Oh, sirloin.
[ Laughs ]
Sorry.
Ryder, are you
catching all this?
Yes.
There you go. Hi, Loretta.
Lori's supervising
the filming at this point.
Just the tomato sauce
or everything?
Both of them.
They're all together.
Okay.
Now you got
to add the peas.
Got it. All right,
so, a couple of eggs.
Can you whisk them,
or you want me to do it?
Like...
Watch yourself.
What next?
You gonna have to take the
rice and put it in your hands.
All right. With the Parmesan
and the Pecorino,
take a little bit of this meat
with the peas,
right in the center.
Correct.
Wrap this over.
Get a little bit more rice.
Put the mozzarella first.
Oh, gosh. These aren't
gonna be small.
So, I got a little base there.
I got a little top.
Fold that over the top
like so.
Correct. Now, the round one
are like Palermo-style.
Huh?
The round one are the one
that they make in Palermo.
Was I supposed
to make different?
No, no, it's fine.
I'm just telling you
there is two different ways.
What is the way you make them?
I do it like that, too.
It's fine.
[ Laughs ]
Benny, you're not gonna do
bad like this, right?
No.
Benny is a champ.
How many come with an order,
Luig?
One, four. [ Laughs ]
Depend
how many you want.
We sell them one at a time,
so...
Ryder,
his answer was, "One, four."
Ryder should be over here
doing this with me,
but Ryder's
running the cameras.
And Ryder's laughing
at me the whole time.
The key is to make sure that
we don't have too much rice,
but enough to seal it shut.
We're gonna go
into the egg wash?
In the egg, correct.
Am I supposed to have
the oil hot, Luigi?
It's supposed to be
at 350.
Were you gonna tell me
to have oil hot, Luigi?
After you were done
breading it.
It's not a restaurant, Luigi.
I'm at my house, in the patio.
It's not really frozen.
You're fake freezing.
[ Laughter ]
Ryder, quit laughing.
Ryder thinks this is hysterical.
All right, so, now
into the bread crumbs.
So, I'm just gonna float
these in lightly
so they don't just
drop to the bottom.
I can't wait to taste these.
When we come back,
it's Luigi's arancini
and then my buddy Benny Lin.
"Triple-D: Takeout"
in a bit.
Yeah, throw them inside.
Dude.
You're killing me, Luigi.
[ Both laugh ]
♪♪
Welcome back, everybody.
We're doing
a little "Triple-D" takeout.
Got some of my favorite
"Triple-D" chefs
from around the country --
Niko and Sikey,
Voula, Benny, and Jay Hajj.
Chef Luigi out of Pizzeria Luigi
in San Diego
sent me
some delicious arancini.
And look at these.
Fantastic,
golden and delicious.
Luigi, is this how
it should look?
Yes. Correct.
Okay, Ryder, get that
shot right there.
That looks amazing.
♪♪
I got to tell you,
it's light, it's creamy.
It's got tons of beef flavor.
A little touch of tomato.
That's your mom's recipe,
isn't it?
She totally
helped me out with that.
Well done. Besides the fact
that I had to drag
all of the descriptions
out of you
and get oil hot,
I will tell you what --
It was worth all of that.
It is delicious, Luigi.
This is how you
do arancini, man.
All right, Benny,
you're chomping at the bit.
I know you want to talk.
We were all the way
in North Pole, Alaska,
doing a special "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives" edition.
When was that?
2009.
I'm gonna take an elbow
to the teeth.
Bam!
Aah!
Okay.
He's Chuck Norris
and Emeril at the same time.
Pour into the plate
and serve.
He's an artist, too.
Look at this.
Here's your chopsticks.
[ Laughs ]
I use fork.
[ Laughing ]
"I use a fork."
What's going on at Pagoda?
You know, everybody's
quarantined at the house.
So we do deliveries
and takeout.
MAN: We're here at Pagoda's
in North Pole,
getting our order to go.
♪♪
All right, Benny,
I said one dish.
[ Laughter ]
This doesn't feel like
one dish, Benny.
Ah! [ Laughs ]
Here's a bunch of masks.
You're the best, brother.
Thank you. Thank you.
I'm gonna take these down
to the local hospital.
Look at this.
Directions with pictures.
Benny Lin.
Bang Bang shrimp.
Benny, I give you
an A in organization, dude.
I made some rice already.
What else do I have to do here?
The Bang Bang sauce.
Okay, so mix
all these together?
Yeah.
We've got shredded coconut.
You don't do the whole thing.
You just put, like,
a couple of spoons.
A couple of spoons
soy sauce.
That's too much soy sauce.
Two spoons, okay?
Hey, Benny.
Have you met Luigi?
[ Laughter ]
What size spoon, Benny?
Tablespoon.
Is that good?
Yes.
How much mayonnaise?
Put two spoons.
Yeah, two spoon lime juice.
The hot chili sauce --
two spoons.
The sweet chili sauce --
five or six spoons.
Now mix that up.
And what's going on
with the shrimp here, Benny?
So, I get 16 to 18 big shrimps,
peeled, deveined.
I boil it already
for a little bit.
Then I coat it
with cornstarch.
He has these little
techniques like this.
It's not a big, thick,
heavy batter.
You want to make sure
each piece of shrimp have the...
Separate?
Yeah, separate
and have the...
Cornstarch on it.
Yep.
[ Both laugh ]
I'm gonna fry it?
Yes. You have to fry them.
Sorry.
I forget to tell you
to turn the fire on.
I did. Since Luigi, I've been
just keeping everything on.
How long are they gonna
take to cook, Benny?
Just, like,
three, four minute
until golden brown.
Boil the veggies. They sit
on a plate, four corners.
And then we made
this Bang Bang sauce.
I'll pour this
on top of the shrimp,
I would assume, Benny?
Yes. Just mixed up
with the sauce.
And then right over the top?
Come on, Ryder. Catch that shot.
Here we go.
Oh, Benny.
Oh!
That's what I'm talking about!
Well done, Guy.
Thank you.
I am right back at Pagoda.
Wait a second.
I need chopsticks.
You didn't send the chopsticks,
Benny? Come on.
I forget
to send the chopsticks.
I don't use chopsticks.
I use a fork.
Way to throw him
under the bus, Luigi.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
This is outrageous.
There's a crispiness
to the prawn,
just for a little touch
of the cornstarch.
There's just enough
coating on it
that it really grabs
onto the sauce.
See what I'm saying, Ryder?
Take a look at that.
The veggies are
a nice little touch.
But it is exactly that --
It's Bang Bang.
It's a little sweet.
It's a little heat.
It's got some great crunch.
Well done, man.
Thank you.
So, before we go to break,
I got to give a shout-out
to all the men and women
behind the scenes
that are making this happen.
Todd and Sean and Cesar,
Citizen Pictures in Denver,
everybody that's at Match Cut
in Minneapolis.
Let me introduce you to them.
Say "hi," everybody.
As we go into break -- and
we'll come back for Jay Hajj --
everybody, big round
of applause
for the team for making
"Triple-D: Takeout" happen.
All right? Thank you very much,
and we'll see you in a bit.
I'm gonna finish the shrimp.
Keep clapping.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Welcome back, everybody.
"Triple-D Takeout"
here at the Fieri compound
in Northern California.
Some of our favorite
Triple-D chefs have joined.
I asked them, "Send me some of
your favorite dishes
during
this very difficult time."
First, we had our buddy Luigi
from San Diego,
and then
the one and only Benny Lin
from North Pole, Alaska.
And now, from Boston,
a guy named Jay Hajj
that has a restaurant
called Mike's City Diner.
Jay, when did we shoot you?
We shot
in July 2007.
Now, do you eat this
with a...
Is there, like,
a contraption?
Well,
when there's gravy in it,
it's best to eat it
with a fork and knife.
I got the gravy,
the stuffing.
That stands up there
in the best turkey sandwiches
I've ever had.
Get the handcart.
I'm ready to get to my car.
What's going on
at Mike's City Diner?
We're doing takeout.
The takeout business
is very strong.
And we're doing delivery,
keeping as many people
working as possible.
Ah, you're awesome.
All right, Jay.
Most people packed it
in some kind of Styrofoam.
You just sent
a real cooler.
Yes. I couldn't find
these fancy boxes
that Luigi
and Benny Lin found.
I used a whole roll
of duct tape on it.
Yeah, I can tell, buddy.
Of course,
Jay wouldn't miss...
I want to give you a few things
to remember me by.
Jay wouldn't miss
an opportunity
to promote
the Jay Hajj boxing gym.
Thank you, brother.
All right, sauces. Pita.
We're gonna be doing
kofta kebabs today
with some fattoush salad.
What do you want me
to start with first, brother?
Let's mix
the kofta first.
The kebabs?
The kebabs.
What does "kofta" mean?
It's just the name of
that particular ground lamb
with seasoning,
and you kind of shape it
into a long sausage
around the skewer,
and that's what
makes it the kebab.
All right.
Let's start with
the ground lamb.
Put it in a bowl.
Okay.
Flatten it around
the bowl a bit.
Ryder took
his child labor law/union break,
and now there she is.
Camera operator Lori.
You're doing a fine job.
Okay, so, the lamb's
in the bowl. Next?
Okay. There's onions
and garlic and spices --
allspice, cinnamon,
ginger, cumin, and salt.
All of that in there.
What next?
Chopped parsley.
That's a lot of parsley.
Yeah.
All right, now mix it well,
like you're making a meatloaf.
Got it. And where is
this recipe from, Jay?
Actually,
it's my mother's recipe.
Every family does it a little
different in the old country.
The old country.
Where is that?
Lebanon.
How many on one skewer?
One. It's gonna be, like,
about 8 inches.
Like so, Jay?
Looks good, actually.
Make sure you put it
on a well-oiled, seasoned grill.
Okay, hang on a second.
I got to get my camera girl
to come over and get a shot.
There you go.
[ Laughs ]
We're now making harissa,
Jay?
We're
making harissa aioli.
Yes, sir.
Some roasted red peppers.
Got it. I see the habaneros
and the Fresnos. Got it.
Just a little.
I know you like heat, so...
Well, they're all
in there now, Jay.
Put four cloves
of garlic.
Now, do you have, like,
a little cup of spices?
Caraway,
cumin, and dried mint.
I've already toasted
all of that for you,
so just throw it right in.
Okay.
I sent you a squeeze
bottle of oil.
Okay.
As it's spinning, you pour
the oil in slowly.
Got it. All blended up
nice and thick, Jay.
Beautiful.
And now I am toasting
this bread.
Do not toast the pita.
Just warm it up.
Give it
a very light crisp.
Okay. It's got
And now the fattoush.
Fattoush is almost, like,
the signature Lebanese salad.
Romaine lettuce, parsley,
mint, and watercress.
Pour that in a bowl
with the onions,
tomatoes, cucumbers,
and radishes.
Okay.
In a dressing cup,
I sent you some lemon juice.
Sumac, lemon juice,
olive oil, and garlic.
Throw it on top of the salad
and toss it.
Did you put the toasted pita
in, as well, or no?
Nope, but I will, Jay,
because you said so.
[ Laughs ]
Let's put each one
of those flatbreads in a plate.
Spread a little
tzatziki sauce on it.
Put the kebab
right in the middle.
Okay.
We have the tahini
in a squeeze bottle.
Give it a little squirt,
like, zigzag.
Do the same
with the harissa aioli.
And some pickled turnip.
Just serve the fattoush
next to it.
How'd I do?
You did fantastic.
That's better
than I could do.
What do you think, Guy?
♪♪
This is dynamite, bro.
You start on this, and you can
just really start to understand
how wonderful
Lebanese food is.
From the toasted spices,
to the sumac
in the dressing,
to the pita croutons.
Cooking the kebab
on an open grill like this,
good heat, good spice...
♪♪
The sweetness that you get
from the harissa,
but also the heat --
bro, juxtaposition
all over the place.
Lights-out dish, bro.
Thank you.
So, three great chefs have
served up fantastic meals.
We got one more to go.
When we come back,
our friends out of Seattle,
Voula and the boys.
We'll see you in a bit.
♪♪
I'm glad you guys
all made it back
because I am just about into
a food coma
here on my "Triple-D: Takeout"
with four of my favorite chefs
from
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Out of the four restaurants
that we're featuring today,
I believe that the OG of the OG
goes to Voula's Offshore Cafe,
back at May 5th, 2007.
See me work?
Skill.
Yeah, thank you.
The skill.
Can we get that in slo-mo?
[ Distorted audio ]
Okay.
[ Bell dings ]
Order up.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
My two buddies Niko and Sikey,
and they come
from an awesome mom.
Thank you.
I don't get that every time
on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Drives."
You don't?
No, I don't walk in
and get a hug.
Thank goodness,
because...
I always like handsome man,
baby.
Well, the last time I was there
was for "Triple-D Nation."
I saw the huge expansion, and
the restaurant looks fantastic.
But you know who looks
really fantastic?
Voula, you look fantastic.
How are you?
Very good.
Thank you, Guy.
Are you doing
any delivery?
NIKOS:
We do have delivery.
It's just, we're
not known for it,
so it's just
building up slowly.
I like to sign at the top --
"Open for carryout."
And thank you very much
for what you sent me.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Oh, it's the lost Ark.
[ Laughter ]
Sent you a couch.
Huh? That is awesome.
Is that food in here?
Grape leaves.
Thank you, Voula.
You sent me a serving platter.
NIKOS: Turn it over.
[ Laughter ]
Ah!
Oh, I got it.
There you go.
Ah, it's awesome.
All right, guys.
I know that we're getting
into a French dip,
which I think "French dip"
might be my middle name.
I see that I have a big,
beautiful piece of prime rib
that you guys have already
pre-cooked for me.
Walk me through
what you did to it.
We coated it with some
Worcestershire sauce,
and then Montreal seasoning
to create the crust.
Roasted it off at 350
for about two hours.
Fantastic. How thin do
we want to slice this?
Number five
on a slicer.
The fact that you think
I have a slicer,
I'm really impressed with,
because I do.
This is my slicer that Jay Hajj
gave me my birthday.
Wow.
How beautiful is that!
VOULA: That's great.
He look like his right arm
is bigger than the left.
[ Laughter ]
All those muscles.
-Look how thin that is.
-Oh, that's beautiful, buddy.
You see that? All right,
so, how do we make the jus?
NIKOS: Pour 1/4 cup
of the red wine
inside of the pan
over there.
Get it to a high boil
and reduce it by half.
Okay. Now the beef base.
A bunch of thyme,
some water. Garlic's down.
Now drop in the onions?
Yes.
What do I got next?
Start your fries, maybe?
They've been soaked
in cold water.
They've been
strained twice.
Then they've been blanched for
two minutes and then chilled.
Great. Toasted my bread.
And how much cheese
on the bread?
You've got American Swiss.
We're gonna put
two slices.
Put three. Come on.
-Do it up. Put three.
-Do it up.
I'm gonna throw this
in the oven
just to melt
that cheese a little bit.
We're gonna need
to incorporate the sour cream
with the horseradish sauce.
Got it.
♪♪
I like
that horseradish kick.
Fries are cooking up nicely.
Tastes like baked potato
on the inside,
nice and crunchy
on the outside.
This jus -- delicious.
So, I'll drop in the prime rib
just long enough to get hot.
Grab out my bread.
Beautiful
caramelized onions.
The horseradish sour cream.
Grab some of this jus.
♪♪
How's that look, Voula?
Well, you do so good job,
I'd hire you.
A little dip into the jus.
Let it soak.
♪♪
Oh, good. Look at him.
Yeah.
Being the French dip aficionado,
there's not a thing going on
that isn't 100%.
I mean, you got
the horseradish sour cream,
the tang of the Swiss.
You got all that jus,
all the fat from the meat,
just rendering
down inside of it.
[ Laughter ]
I guess there's none
for anybody else.
You've all rocked it.
You've gone above and beyond.
But I am gonna give a best dish,
and I will give $500
in the name of the restaurant
that gets best dish to RERF.
That's the Restaurant
Employee Relief Fund.
So, $500 in the name of...
♪♪
...Jay Hajj
and Mike's City Diner.
-Yeah!
-Well done, Jay.
FIERI:
There you go, champ.
Listen, Benny, Jay, Luigi,
Voula, Sikey, Niko,
I got to tell you something --
It was all delicious.
You are the "Triple-D" OGs.
Love you guys.
Thanks for making it.
Okay? Take care.
-Thank you, thank you.
-Love you.
♪♪
This is ridiculous.
Not in my contract.
-Ah, gee.
-Oh, no.