So when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D","
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks,
I got to be hon--
Can we just please go
to a restaurant
at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner, huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know some
"Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got a funky waffle
coming from the funk
masters themselves,
straight out
of Syracuse.
This should be, like, a belt
buckle in Flavortown.
And the ultimate grown-up
mac and cheese
from a dynamite cafe
in Cleveland.
If you sold it
by the tanker truck,
I would be
your first customer.
Plus, my buddy Greg
and Pinky's in Charlotte
is sending some green chili pork
with an island twist.
Dude, that's the bomb.
And our boy Gorilla
nearby in Pacifica
is heading over to drop off
some outrageous smoked turkey.
This is crazy.
And on top of it all,
they're gonna
video-conference in
to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
I like the way you think.
Exactly.
This is
"Triple-D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Alright, so here we are,
Gorilla, Greg, Adam,
and is that Heather?
Hi, Heather.
Hi, buddy.
We got Northern California,
Charlotte, North Carolina,
Syracuse, and Cleveland.
So only one West Coast
representative.
One West Coast, yeah.
We started this whole
"Triple-D Takeout"
because we went to have
something great to eat
besides me cooking
all the time.
And this just kind of
turned into a new habit.
Why not call our favorite
"Triple-D" chefs
from around the country and say,
"Send us out something new
that you're doing"?
It's going to Flavortown.
Who wants to go first?
Adam?
Oh, yeah.
Go, Adam.
Funk 'n Waffle.
Now, you're not
at the same location
that we first met you
and the Sophistafunk crew.
♪ Wait, wait, wait ♪
We're in the basement
of this funky little joint.
And here's this crazy dude
with these waffle makers
making these incredible
dishes.
ADAM: Breakfast waffles
and lunch waffles
and fried chicken
and waffles.
He made this
Thanksgiving waffle.
And that starts out
with our stuffing.
That is just in
so many ways weird.
And I'm like, "I don't know
this is gonna work."
Shut the front door.
Oh, my gosh.
That is funkin' ridiculous.
Where's this new location at?
ADAM: Armory Square,
which is the heart
of Syracuse.
Are the boys around,
by the way?
The boys are around.
We're gonna drop
a little
Sophistafunk for you
while you're opening
things up.
[ Laughing ]
Look at Heather
with the horn.
Alright. You ready?
♪ It's funky ♪
[ Laughing ]
♪ We gonna find it ♪
♪ At "Diners, Drive-Ins,
& Dives" ♪
Hell yeah.
You guys
just keep playing.
We're not gonna cook
anything today.
-Look at that.
-We love you.
Hey, very kind, guys.
Really appreciate it.
So I sent you this brand-new
chicken Parm waffle.
The waffle's
made of spaghetti.
Ooh!
So we're gonna make
a chicken Parmesan,
put it on a crispy bed
of noodle waffle?
Yeah.
How do you want us
to start this, brother?
You might as well get
the chicken going.
We sent you
some chicken tenders there.
Now, has the chicken
been brined ahead of time?
Yes. In water and salt,
overnight.
You're gonna
see the dredge.
We're gonna want to mix
all those parts together.
Flour, paprika, ground black
pepper, cayenne, bread crumbs
and kosher salt.
Get this, after we
aired on "Triple-D,"
like, seven years ago,
a local middle school
home-ec teacher started
a Funk 'n Waffles unit,
and they come up
with their own waffles.
And they called me in
to judge the waffles.
And this was
the winning waffle.
What's the name of the school?
Wellwood Middle School.
Big shout-out.
Nice job on this, team.
And now
you're gonna want to mix
whole milk and some buttermilk
waffle batter.
Got it.
Dunk those
raw chicken tenders...
And then go into this flour
and bread-crumb mixture.
Oil at 350?
Yeah, we've been
doing it 350.
Okay, I got pasta.
And the milk.
Yeah, the milk.
Yep.
Next up?
There's two pieces
of cheese.
I've got you the Pecorino
and the Reggiano.
And just drop them in like
this in whole big chunks?
No, you're
gonna shave them.
Really good cheese you sent me,
by the way. I can smell it.
Oh, yeah.
I'm not messing around.
Fresh cracked pepper
and about a tablespoon
and a half of sea salt.
Two eggs for that
whole mess there.
And you should warm up
the tomato sauce.
No waffle batter
or anything inside of this?
No, that's it.
Where's the waffle batter?
You just had it.
I'm putting some.
Listen, I'm breaking outside
of this a little bit.
[ Laughing ] He's just tossing
it in there.
I like my idea.
You sent me the ingredients.
I'll cook it my way.
He's winging it.
I think the waffle batter
is gonna give a little
consistency
in between some of the noodles
because just that
little bit of egg --
This is my opinion.
Let me see.
Put a little canola
down on this.
Yeah. Just grease it up
a little bit.
And now overstuff it...
Uh-huh.
...so that it fills
all the grids.
You want to spin it back
halfway so it's locked.
Yes. Just like that.
Oh, I got another side, too.
Yeah.
Chop a whole nother one.
I didn't know that
there was two!
Double down.
Nice work on that chicken,
Hunter.
Zoom in
on that chicken.
You should have some
mozzarella cheese
that you're gonna melt
on those tenders.
Oh, it's looking
gorgeous.
[ Waffle whistling ]
Dude, it is making
a hot-mess noise over here.
Oh, yeah. I mean,
that's probably because
you added
that batter to it, bro.
What's the batter with that?
You remember what
that sound's called?
[ Waffle whistles ]
What is going on
right now?
It's urgling.
Urgling is the term?
Is that what we're looking for?
That looks good.
Sauce, then tenders,
and then some parsley
and grated cheese.
Very nice.
Save me a bite.
So if there was anybody
questioning whether or not
there was gonna be
any pasta in that...
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
Mmm!
This is a cross
between pasta, lasagna,
garlic bread.
It is the best chicken waffle
I've ever had in my life.
Awesome.
The noodles are just
crammed together
and a little bit of the batter
holding it together.
Oh, yeah.
Get in there, Ryder.
It's got great tomato sauce,
delicious chicken.
This should be, like, a belt
buckle in Flavortown.
[ Laughter ]
Yeah.
This is a little outside
of my bandwidth.
I'm not a big waffle maker.
This now becomes a staple.
You have leftover pasta,
you got to do it this way.
Or better yet, order out from
Funk 'n Waffle out of Syracuse.
"Triple-D Takeout"
with the Fieri boys, backyard.
We'll see in a bit.
Get some more sauce.
Let's fix this one up right now.
Welcome back.
"Triple-D Takeout."
Hanging out here at the house
and some of my favorite chefs
in the country
sending us outrageous food
and outrageous music.
Big thanks to the Sophistafunk
team over at Funk 'n Waffle,
the spaghetti waffle
chicken and Parm.
Dude, I mean, what?
I had to make it
an extra-long commercial
just because I had to take
a brief nap at the pool.
And to go along with it,
the entertainment --
We got Gorilla, Greg,
and representing Cleveland,
the one and only
Chef Heather at Lucky's.
She's so excited.
She's still dancing.
How long ago was it
that we shot Lucky's?
2009.
GUY: So you make the bread,
you make the corned beef.
You make the sauerkraut.
HEATHER: Yeah. In-house.
GUY: Look at that.
I don't even know that
I'm worthy to eat this.
They should have a shot of that
in the Louvre.
Mmm!
I don't know that you should
accept money for these.
Bring us your first born.
How are things in the world
of Lucky's in Cleveland?
Doing good.
We're hanging in there.
You know,
they're still coming,
and we're still cooking.
You need that, Guy.
You need that one.
Ryder, what are they?
They're bubbles.
Yes.
Right now we have a plaque
on the patio
that says, When in need,
ring the bell
and we'll bring you
bubbles."
And that's
what we do here.
Oh, those are awesome.
Crowd, join in.
♪♪
Who-o-o-a.
Look at that.
Welcome to
"Triple-D Takeout," folks.
I hope we're gonna cook today.
Did you send us food?
Yes. We're making baked
macaroni and cheese
with rendered bacon
plus applesauce.
H, what do we start with first?
Pull out
the sweet cream.
I sent you two portions.
Okay, two different pans,
Hunter.
We'll make them both
at the same time.
I love it.
And then you're gonna add
1/4 teaspoon of kosher salt
and some fresh
cracked black pepper.
Okay.
And there is also a container
of smoked paprika.
You're just gonna put
a little pinch in each one,
add sour cream
and Parmesan to each pan.
Got it.
And we can't add
another ingredient
until that comes up
to a rapid bubble.
That's when you're going
to add your mozzarella,
Brie and cheddar.
And once
that's incorporated,
you're gonna divide
that container
of chopped, rendered bacon
between the two pots.
Add your pasta.
I've never had Brie
in a mac and cheese.
HEATHER: You know,
when I was growing up,
my mom owned
a catering company,
and she always had
little pieces of cheese
left over
from the fancy cheese boards.
And so when she would make
our mac and cheese,
she would be able
to throw the Brie in there.
And we had applesauce
with everything.
I love applesauce.
So it tastes like that
quintessential bite
you have
with a cheese board,
with a chunk of Brie
and an apple.
-Whoo!
-Oh!
Ryder, do you like applesauce?
RYDER: I mean, it depends.
School applesauce is not good.
Heather, break down
the applesauce for me.
We get whatever apples our
farmers are in need of moving.
Put them in a stock pot
with just a teeny bit of water
and that apple dictates
what ingredients we're adding.
But mostly it's white sugar,
brown sugar,
fresh lemon juice
and salt.
And just cook it super slow
until all the apples
break down.
And then put it through
a food mill.
I'll tell you something.
That is the bomb applesauce.
Thank you, my brother.
I'm going to Cleveland
next week
to get me some of that.
I will love that.
Okay, Heather,
so the game plan is
take these bread crumbs
on there.
Hunter, to the oven.
Let's do it.
Alright. We'll put
a little crisp on top with that.
You'll come back
and watch us eat.
We're making two of the dishes
this time,
so we don't fight over it.
"Triple-D Takeout"
at the Fieris.
We'll see it a bit.
Alright. Let's get this cleaned
up and ready to feed.
♪♪
Welcome back
to "Triple-D Takeout."
Hanging out with Hunter
and Ryder in the backyard.
We got some amazing dishes
that some of our favorite
"Triple-D" chefs
from all over the place
have sent to us.
One of the things
that's going on here
is we are gonna go
for a best dish.
Now, I just will remind you,
that does not include
cash or prizes.
No, absolutely not.
It's simply
just bragging rights.
So far, Adam, Funk 'n Waffle
delivered a pasta waffle
with a marinara
and some fried chicken
that was rock-star, legendary,
out of bounds.
Our good friend Heather
from Lucky's in Cleveland
sent us all the makings
of a mac and cheese.
This has got bacon.
It's got Brie.
It's got mozz.
It's got cheddar. It's got Parm.
And it's got a nice crisp
up on top.
But it is hot.
Oh, man.
She's setting the bar high.
There's a specific way
we tell people
in the cafe to eat this.
If you put your fork
in the applesauce first
and then dive into
the good, sexy mac and cheese,
the applesauce cools
down the mac and cheese
so you can eat it.
Oh, yeah.
♪♪
I don't think I've ever had mac
and cheese with applesauce,
and it's fantastic.
I can't eat mac and cheese
without applesauce now.
I know it's good
when Ryder says,
"Alright, I'm coming over."
I got to get this big
old beauty shot here.
He's gonna wear half of it.
The pasta is cooked perfectly.
A really nice assortment
of cheeses.
The sweet cream.
It just balances out
a little bit.
The rendered bacon already
in there, nice and crispy.
Those little nuggets.
The applesauce --
if you sold it
by the tanker truck,
I would be your
first customer.
Ryder said this is
his favorite
mac and cheese of all time.
What?
My favorite dish
from, like, all the shows
combined.
Out of all
the "Triple-D Takeouts"
that we've done, so far,
this is his favorite dish.
Can you do me a favor?
Give him a big squish for me.
Sure thing. Right here.
Yes, Hunt--
No, not that kind of squish.
Thank you very much, Ryder.
I appreciate that.
GUY: As these two retire
to enjoying that by the pool,
my brother Greg from Pinky's
all the way in Charlotte,
North Carolina.
Still got the Bug on the roof?
GREG: Oh, yeah.
Bug's still on the roof.
Rocking and rolling, man.
GUY:
Three 5-ounce patties.
And why do you call it
the Triple "G" burger?
Because it was Triple "G"
Volkswagen repair.
See, I thought when you called
this the Triple "G" burger,
it was
"Guy's Grocery Games."
Even in Charlotte,
it's got to be about Guy.
[ Laughs ]
Here we go.
You're attacking
this thing.
It looks like a coyote
got ahold of it.
[ Laughing ]
GUY: Alright, Pinky.
GREG:
Alright. Top box there.
Just a bunch of swag.
That's awesome.
Ryder, get a shot
at this.
That's the patron saint
of Flavortown.
I'm gonna put it
right over here
at the Flavortown
memorials.
Nice.
Tell us about this
great dish we're getting into.
I'm bringing the green
chili pork sandwich.
What do I have here, brother?
Marinated pork loin.
What's it been marinated in?
Pineapple juice,
roasted poblano
and diced jalapeños,
cilantro, soy sauce,
little bit of olive oil.
How do you want us
to start off with this?
Get your
frying pan hot.
And that's got just
enough oil in it
where it won't stick.
So you'll get a good sear.
Alright. So what are we gonna do
with the pineapple now?
Cut them about a quarter
inch slices
and just sear 'em up
a little bit.
These big, huge, monster
pieces are what go on this?
-Yeah.
-Wowsers.
And there's little bits
of poblanos and jalapeños.
Don't be scared to throw
a few of them in there,
sear 'em up.
Poblanos and jalapeños.
I was gonna try to talk
without subtitles,
but I'll just let loose.
You just gonna let it happen?
Let loose.
Toast the buns up.
What's this little concoction
you sent me right here?
That is
the Jamaican relish.
It's sweet red peppers
and pickled watermelon rind.
-Ooh.
-Pickled watermelon rind?
Jamaican me hungry.
[You making me]
Dude, that's the bomb.
Take three quarters
of the mayonnaise
and mix it in
with all of the relish.
That will be sauce
to put on the bun.
Got it.
That's the kind of sear
you're looking for, brother?
Oh, yeah.
Nice caramelization on that.
And then lay some
of the arugula.
Cheese will go on top
of the seared pork.
Put the pineapple on top
of the Swiss cheese.
Looking good.
I could smell it from here.
The bun is just dying
under the pressure of this,
by the way.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
He's stepping back.
You have just
the right amount
of pineapple juice.
Great with the Swiss.
You need the tang.
This Jamaican relish,
whatever you call it.
Nice little tang.
Pork loin is lean.
Get some extra fat from
the mayonnaise coming through.
You got so much heat and
so much flavor and so much sauce
and so much pow going on.
So much pow!
Ridiculous.
I mean, delicious, on point.
Thank you, brother.
HUNTER: That's a good burger.
It's fresh.
We've got to clean this up.
We got to take
a little bit of a rest.
And when we come back,
don't go anywhere
because we're bringing to you
the barbecue king
of Pacifica.
Gorilla's up next.
See you in a bit.
Go, Gorilla.
Oh, welcome back
to "Triple-D Takeout."
I got to be honest
with you, folks,
the whole idea of this
was to get some delicious food
from around the country
so we didn't have to do all
the cooking here at the house.
I thought it was to eat
the meals throughout the day,
not all in one sitting.
Between
the spaghetti waffle
done with the fried chicken
and the tomato sauce
over to the mac and cheese
extraordinaire,
then on to the North Carolina
marinated pork sandwich
with the grilled pineapple,
I got to tell you something,
guys.
Gorilla, please tell me that
you sent us a yogurt parfait.
[ Laughter ]
Alright, Gorilla.
How are things
at the big, orange boxcar?
GORILLA: We're alright.
We're holding tight.
Check it out.
Pacifica, California.
You'll see it.
A big, orange boxcar.
And you can come
get some pork ribs.
[ Laughing ]
Gorilla, thank you
for making the drop-off.
You brought it up yourself
in the Gorilla wagon.
Enjoy. Peace.
I hope this is a salad.
You can't honestly expect
Gorilla to send you a salad.
Looks like a salad to me.
No, no.
Surprise, surprise.
Good! Bananas!
Thanks.
Thanks, everybody,
for tuning in to...
There's my lunch.
I was looking for that yesterday
when I dropped it off.
[ Laughs ]
Nice.
"Back off 6 feet."
I got to be honest, dude, I've
eaten your barbecue for years.
I don't want a white shirt.
Mmm. Delicious.
I'm gonna have to go home
and shampoo my goatee.
What exactly are we making?
"Triple-D Takeout"
gorilla berry,
smoked turkey sandwich.
The name just rolls.
It's just so easy to say.
Alright. So tell me about
this turkey breast, brother.
What's the story here?
It's about a 3-pound
turkey breast.
I brined it overnight
in my rub,
believe it or not,
dried it,
seasoned it with my rub,
smoked it with almond wood.
Delicious.
Dude, that's some good
turkey right there.
Tender, juicy, nice little smoke
with that almond.
It's not super heavy.
It is fantastic.
Thanks.
We're gonna drop this
in the wood-fired oven.
What's going up next?
Get your rolls,
cut them.
And then the coleslaw.
I have handcut
red cabbage,
green cabbage
and carrots.
I sent you our house coleslaw
dressing to mix with it.
The barbecue sauce can go
in the squirt bottle.
That's an easy vessel
for application.
An easy vessel
Thank you, Gorilla.
GORILLA:
Toast off that roll.
Say a minute or two.
Beautiful.
Grab some of the gorilla berry
habanero compote.
Could you explain
what a gorilla berry is?
A gorilla berry
is actually a cranberry.
Okay.
So down with some
of the compote.
A lot more. You got to be
real generous with that compote.
And then
we put the bird down.
HEATHER: Ryder is on top
of that camera.
I love it.
GUY: No mayo on this,
right?
No mayo.
You're gonna get
the mayonnaisey part
from the coleslaw.
The ma-- The what?
The mayonnaisey.
Mayonnaisey part?
Or the food lube.
There you go.
And then
give it barbecue sauce.
Cut it on a bias,
give it a good smash.
And then there you go.
-Good smash.
-Mangia, baby.
See what you think.
Oh, man.
Mmm.
Can someone ship
the other one to me?
I see a little bit
of a haunch,
but I don't see
the step back Pinky got.
Oh, there it goes.
Okay, okay.
It's Thanksgiving sandwich
but with that little spice that
you're getting
from the habanero cranberry...
Gorilla berry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This being the first time that
I'm making the smoked turkey,
gorilla berry, gorilla
barbecue sandwich,
it's like hearing a song
for the first time.
You all sent us dishes
that were so unique
and so creative and so you.
This is crazy.
There is a clock
ticking in my head right now,
and it's a countdown
to a food coma.
Now, as you remember,
there is gonna be
a best dish here.
I don't know who it is.
There's no cash.
There's no prizes.
Full-blown bragging rights.
So just hold, please.
I need a big or a shower.
Let's do it.
Alright.
I've got who I want to have
do it.
Uh-oh, here we go.
Dad, so you know,
on some shows,
they have, like,
the Golden Buzzer?
Someone buzzes and says
their contestant wins
no matter what.
You're gonna call
your Golden Buzzer?
Yep.
Ryder.
Alright. Golden Buzzer.
The winner of today's
"Triple-D Takeout" is...
Drumroll.
♪♪
The macaroni and cheese.
Mac and cheese!
Heather and Lucky's!
Thatagirl, Heather,
all the way from Cleveland!
Thank you so much,
and I hope this inspires
everybody that's home,
get great takeout and delivery
from your favorite restaurants
because, Lord knows,
after everything
we've been through,
they definitely can use
the support.
You guys were fantastic.
Thanks a lot.
Love you guys.
See you next week.
"Triple-D Takeout." Adios.
Alright. I'm going to sleep.
You guys clean it up.
Ryder, clean it up.
I'm leaving.
♪ "Triple-D Takeout" edition ♪
♪ It's okay ♪
♪ We gonna find it ♪
♪ At "Diners, Drive-Ins,
& Dives" ♪