Man, it sure is nice
to have the Camaro home.
It's never here.
That's right.
And you know,
since we're quarantined...
The car's quarantined.
...the car's quarantine.
Now, we've been making
some fantastic meals
here at the Fieri house,
but what do we really want?
I just want
to go out to eat.
Well, we can't
go out to eat.
But we can get takeout,
and I know some Triple D joints
that would love
to send it to us.
FIERI: From Fairhope, Alabama,
Panini Pete is going to send
some paella fritters.
Bro, this is dynamite.
And then our buddy John Conley
coming out of Arizona
is going to send us
some kind of a crazy tamale.
This is exactly
what we wanted it to be.
Nina from Forte in Vegas
is going to send
this great dumplings.
Take a look at that, huh?
[ Whistles ]
Then from Kansas City, Missouri,
we got our buddy, Stretch,
and he's going to send us some
burnt-end Philly cheese steaks.
This is taking the best
of Philly and the best of KC
and putting them together.
On top of it all, they're going
to video conference in
to give us the true
"Triple D" experience.
You hungry, Hunter?
Very.
Exactly.
This is "Triple D: Takeout."
You missed a spot.
Oh, come on.
♪♪
All right, so here
we are, folks.
These are our first
four chefs joining us for
the special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives:
Takeout."
Here for our virtual meeting,
our culinary adventure,
the one and only, from
Fairhope, Alabama, Panini Pete.
Then out of
Kansas City, Missouri,
there's our boy, Stretch,
with a fine hairdo.
And then he's from Salsa Brava
and Fat Olives,
the one and only John Conley.
And our good friend Nina
from Forte in Las Vegas
where Hunter had
his graduation party.
Huh?
That's some good times.
All right,
so Hunter and I are quarantined
here with Lori and Ryder
here at our house.
And so we asked you
to send us a great dish
that you're currently
working on,
something that's exciting,
that is on the menu
or going
to be on the menu,
so we are prepared,
depending on what fashion
you sent this to us in,
to do a little bit
of heating and warming up.
Hunter, any questions?
Did we start this right?
Yeah.
We're doing great.
We have absolutely no idea
what we're doing,
but this is the reason
we did this.
As chefs
and as restaurant owners
and as people that work
in the industry,
we know how hard
the industry is being hit
and that's why
we're wearing our shirts.
This is the R.E.R.F.,
the Restaurant Employee
Relief Fund.
We've been doing a lot
of fundraising for that
and helping the employees
that are out of work.
Everybody needs a little love,
needs a little support.
And so what we thought
we would do is show everybody
how you could go to some of
your favorite restaurants
and get takeout and enjoy
some of this great food at home.
All right,
so who's going first?
Panini Pete,
give me the update.
What's taking place
in all of the Panini Pete's
and Sunset Pointe Grill
in the Fairhope, Alabama, area?
PETE: All of our places
are shut down.
We did takeout for
a little bit,
and we decided to give
everybody a break.
Go home, be safe.
And where are
you right now?
I'm in Sunset Pointe.
This the place you did in 2017.
That's the snapper throat.
Dig in.
Great, great fish.
It's really good.
You're probably
going to love it.
Look at that nugget.
Done?
I'll go away right now.
Out of bounds.
You're doing it the right way.
FIERI: All right. I said
send me a great dish
that you're doing at your
restaurant for when you reopen.
So I got a big box.
A couple of boxes coming to you.
I don't know
what's in here.
You know, I never
miss an opportunity
to show some love.
Oh!
Nice!
Look at that.
All night, Panini,
we have best dish.
You win.
Thanks a lot, everybody,
for tuning in to
"Diners, Drives & Dives:
Takeout."
There you go.
-That's money.
-That's sick.
-All right, what do we got?
-You ready?
Did you leave anything
in Alabama there, Panini?
I know. I mean, I want to
just try the dish.
I'm going to cook it,
I guess, the whole thing.
PETE: You've got
all the means for
the paella fritter dish, baby.
You take a paella rice
and kind of clash it
with an arancini, make it
a fried little fritter ball.
Ice for a cocktail?
[ Laughs ]
Did you
actually send ice?
It says
"Ice for a cocktail."
That's awesome.
I put the ice in there, too.
So walk me through
the paella rice.
So we started off with just
sauteed some onions and garlic.
We added in the rice
with some stock and saffron.
Chorizo's going in there,
then we have our peas.
Got it. Next up?
Grilled chicken thigh.
Okay.
There should be
a small container
of a sliced green onions.
Manchego cheese has got
to go in there, too.
All right,
mixing it together.
Scramble that egg.
This egg that's in here
that's already cracked,
that's still in the shell,
it's completely gnarly.
[ Groans ]
It was whole when
I put it in there.
I should have
bubble wrapped it.
[ Chuckles ]
If I don't
hate egg enough...
So, basically now, Pete,
you have paid off
your egg dilemma
with the skateboard
and you're at ground zero.
Add that in there as a binder.
Mix it in good.
And then we're going to be able
to roll it into balls.
Bread crumbs?
That's breading mixture.
All you got to do
is dump and stir, baby.
Corn meal.
Yeah.
Everybody in the pool.
Guy, it looks like
complete chaos on this side.
How is it there?
A chaos is
an understatement, Stretch,
but thank you very much
for checking in.
Panini, what do we have here?
Spice for breading?
That goes in
with the breading mix.
I know,
but what are the spices?
It's got salt, pepper.
It's got garlic, cayenne,
paprika, and some dried oregano.
Okay, so Hunter can go ahead
and form these up.
I have some egg wash there.
This is milk that
you sent us here,
and you need an egg
added to that.
There was an egg.
Oh.
No, Panini, they're all broken.
Don't start.
Is this the size
we're looking for?
Yeah, golf ball size
looks perfect.
You got this, Hunter.
Hunter's going to take
the paella ball
with the chorizo.
It's got the cooked
chicken thigh.
It's got the peas,
and you had already hit
that paella
with the saffron,
so it's got
that beautiful color.
Then we're going to go
into this milk and egg wash
into the multi mix
of every ingredient
you possibly have,
and that's going to go together
into the oil at 350.
You got it. Perfect.
Now let's talk about
the romesco sauce.
What do we got, Pete?
Alright, so you got some
roasted red peppers there.
Toasted almonds,
red vinegar.
Some oil down there, as well.
Parsley in there.
Green onions?
Green onions. Yep.
Is that lemon zest?
Yep. Go ahead.
Everybody's
in the pool.
Any salt or pepper
into this Panini?
Yeah, salt and pepper.
And this is
the romesco sauce.
All right, so here's
the deal, everybody.
Panini Pete from
Fairhope, Alabama,
has sent us
a fantastic recipe
that we got to cook
completely ourselves.
Ryder's on the camera.
Hunter's on the paella.
I'm making a romesco.
When we come back,
"Triple D: Takeout"
happening here
at the Fieri house,
and we'll see you in a bit.
Panini, these
better taste awesome.
All right, keep an eye.
Welcome back to
"Triple D: Takeout",
a special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
happening here
in Northern California
at the Fieri house.
I've got my main man
Ryder on the cameras.
I've got Hunter
doing the sous chefing
and co-hosting.
And four of my favorite
"Triple D" chefs
are joining me here
via a video conference.
We got the Panini Pete.
We've got Stretch,
John Conley, and Nina
from Forte in Las Vegas.
We're working
on Panini's recipe,
a paella fritter,
but he didn't make them.
He sent us the ingredients
to make them.
Here's the romesco.
So we usually
a little arugula salad
with a little
vinaigrette.
How do you like our plating
so far, Panini?
You're looking good, man.
You're looking good.
All right.
Little bit of steam
coming off of that.
Mm.
There you go.
How is it, Ryder?
Nice!
Here's what I love about it.
The saffron rice,
perfectly cooked.
The chorizo is nice and salty.
It's got that chorizo
kick that you want.
My favorite part about it is the
manchego and the chicken thigh.
HUNTER: Yeah.
Bro, this is dynamite.
This is paella to go.
I don't think I've had it
in this form, in this style,
this good, good ever.
Congrats, man.
Oh, brah,
thanks, Guy.
Thanks, Hunter.
Good job, man.
I wish you sent all of us
some of that.
Boom, boom, boom.
We knocked it out.
So who's next?
Stretch!
[ Alarm blares ]
How many years ago was it
that we did "Triple D?"
STRETCH: '07.
Did you, because you knew
I was coming today,
fashion your hair
in my style,
or am I following
your lead?
I'm the guy that colors
outside the lines.
I think I'm going to be
dye it red.
I want do
a Bozo the Clown thing.
I like the way
you're rolling.
You are so ridiculous.
I'm sorry, folks.
What's going on in
Kansas City, Stretch?
We are shut down.
We may open back up in a couple
of weeks on the to-goes.
I think I see the box
that looks like yours.
I hope everything
made it.
[ Laughs ]
-Really?
-There's something
wrong with you.
That's what you sent.
HUNTER: Oh?
[ Laughs ]
You see that?
Hopefully there's
some food in there.
So what is the dish
that we're making?
Give me
a little rundown.
STRETCH: So what we're doing
today is our
Grinder's Burnt End Philly
sandwich on an Amoroso roll
shipped in from Philadelphia,
all the way shipped
to California at this point.
Walk me through
the burnt ends.
Gosh, those look good.
So those burnt ends are cooked
along with the brisket
at about 275
for about 5 1/2 hours,
till they hit about 165-ish.
We separate the flat
from the point,
then it's cubed up
with some sauce
and some of
the grinders rub in there.
Then its wrapped, and then
we finish it off till about 205.
And you sent me the flat.
See that nice pink smoke ring
right around there.
Look at Ryder's camera work.
Good job.
Heat this in the pan,
and you'll walk us through this.
Yeah, man,
go for it.
You got onions, peppers.
You can saute in mushrooms,
as well.
Put I'm in the same pan
with that meat.
Cook and caramelize
some of the rendering
of the fat that's coming
from this brisket.
Yes, sir.
Toast the bread off.
What did you
want us to do next?
Little bit of the rub on top.
Hit it with a little bit
of a sauce,
then it goes in the bun.
Okay, so load them up
like this.
There's one for Ryder.
Now we hit it all
with the Cheese Whiz.
But the meat and the onions
and everything are so hot
that it's just going
to melt right on there.
Little barbecue sauce
on top of that.
Dude, this is monster.
That is correct.
That's what you get.
Takeout.
You guys see that?
You got to do
a little hunch on this one.
Good form,
good form.
Get it, Ryder,
get it, man.
I'm gonna break it down
for you.
The brisket is so tender,
great texture.
It's just what you love
about burnt ends.
Then you take this whole
other change of direction.
You get yourself
into cheese.
into Philly.
You get into
this great Amoroso roll.
That melts in your mouth.
I mean, that's unreal.
This is taking the best
of Philly and the best of KC
and putting them
together.
Stretch,
home run, brother.
This is a one way ticket
to Flavortown.
You rocked the house.
But don't go anywhere,
everybody.
We got two more
of our chefs from
"Diner, Drive-Ins & Dives"
coming up.
All right, Hunter.
I'm going to finish my sandwich.
Start cleaning up.
Tell you what, I'm going to
sleep good tonight
with all this food.
So welcome back.
"Triple D: Takeout" hanging out
with the Fieri boys here
in Northern California.
Now, we're just like you.
We're stuck at home.
But we thought we'd make
the best of things,
and we have invited
four of our "Triple D" legends
to come and hang out with us
and send us fantastic food.
Well, we got Panini Pete,
we got Stretch,
got John Conley,
and then Nina.
Now, what's going on
with you guys?
The masks -- I've seen like
six different ones now.
And that brings us to Nina
at Forte, who is drinking.
-[ Laughs ]
-Yes, I love it.
By the way, Nina and my whole
entire production team
thought they would have
a real blast
at my expense playing
this little joke on me
that Nina didn't speak
English very well
and that her father was
this crazy Eastern European guy
who was going to throw me
out of the restaurant.
[ Speaking native language ]
We're having
a little bit of
a cultural intervention
right now.
Now he's storming off.
Some fish.
Yeah, but we've been
here for about 20 years.
So you know we speak
English pretty well.
What's up, man?
No way!
MAN: Yes.
[ Laughter ]
Real funny, ha-ha-ha.
Nina, give us the update.
Are you open?
What's happening in Las Vegas?
Yeah, we are
still open,
but I changed the hours
to Thursday through Saturday,
and we're just doing
curbside pickup and delivery.
And then I started
doing these virtual
cooking classes
with kits.
Well, it's not the official
cooking class,
but what did you send us?
Hunter, to the boxes.
Okay.
Yeah, this is nice
and organized.
See, professionals.
You have to wear that.
You have to wear it.
It's a traditional...
[ Laughs ]
Come on, Hunter, put it on.
It looks good on you.
So what
did you send us?
NINA: It's the pelmeni
and the vareniki.
Pelmeni are the meat dumplings,
and then the vareniki
are the potato dumplings.
How do you
pronounce that?
"Va-ren-iki."
And that actually means boiled,
like something boiled.
What was
the other one?
Pelmeni. So these are very
similar to, like, pierogies.
Okay, so, Hunter, you're going
to make the vareniki.
I'll make the pelmeni.
So if you're going to do
the pelmeni,
you just mix
the ground beef
with the one package
of grated onion.
You just put some pepper,
just a pinch of salt.
And then there should be
a container with beef base,
and then you're going
to mix all that together.
And that'll be your filling.
And how does
Hunter get started?
So, Hunter, you're going to take
the grated potato
and put it in the bowl.
Okay.
And then in the saute pan,
just start sautéing some onions.
And what else does
he add into this?
So potato, onion,
some salt and pepper.
Onions.
Okay. How much salt?
Just like
a pinch of salt.
Beautiful.
Hunter mixes
that one up.
And here we are
into these rolled out
pieces of dough.
And then you're just going
to do a tablespoon
of the filling inside.
And how do you like
to pinch it shut?
Oh, you got a demonstration
right there.
I'm going to do like
a little half-moon.
Put water
just on the ends.
And then you pinch
the middle,
and you
bring them forward.
-Okay.
-And you put both flaps up.
That's beautiful.
Look how beautiful it is.
[ Laughs ]
So pinching it tight.
There we go.
Fold up the flap,
bring it together.
And there we go.
How's that, Nina?
Beautiful.
Huh? Look at that.
Yeah, but the potato,
we do a different shape.
Uh-oh.
[ Laughter ]
So you fold it in half
like the last one.
And then with these
two fingers,
you basically start just
rolling all the way down.
Like that?
You're amazing!
Like that.
Now, what are
we going to do, Nina?
Are we going to go
to boiled water with this?
With salt in it?
Yeah, just put some salt
in some canola oil.
Let these boil
for how long?
So you'll see the skin
start to get a little bit
clearer, and they'll
float to the top.
Okay.
Right here, Hunter.
You ready?
We're landing.
Oh, look how perfectly
those are made.
Okay, so a little green onion
on the potato one.
No, green onion
on the meat ones.
[ Sad trombone plays ]
Couldn't you have
just gone with it, Nina?
Nice.
And where does the dill go?
NINA: On the meat ones.
And the onions
that maybe got
a little extra caramelized
on top of the potatoes?
On the potato, yes.
And then just salt and pepper.
Looks good.
Take a look
at that, huh?
Not bad.
Ryder, get a shot of that.
HUNTER: And the apron.
They look delicious.
♪♪
Nice.
[ Laughs ]
I got to be honest with you.
I think that we did
a pretty good job at it.
They're tender, delicious.
The key to both
is the garnish.
The dill on the meat,
the sour cream makes it.
And the caramelized onion
on the potato
is the win.
That is dynamite.
Even Ryder's shoveling
his face right now.
Yeah, if Ryder's shoveling
his face
and it's not pizza or a taco,
you know that
it's got to be great.
Listen, ladies and gentlemen,
this is going better
than we ever expected.
This is working out
perfect.
This is awesome.
This is perfect.
All right.
I mean, if we didn't have
to do all the prep.
Yeah.
You know?
But we're quarantined,
and there's nobody else
here to do it, so that's
why you've got the camera team.
Lori's doing
hair and makeup,
and Hunter's
wearing the apron.
All right,
who does that leave us?
It leaves us John Conley.
[ Bell dings ]
Coming up.
All right, Ryder,
your turn to wear the apron.
Welcome back.
"Triple D: Takeout" here
at the house
in Northern California.
Hunter is my sous chef
and co-producer.
What we've been doing is
doing takeout
with our favorite
"Triple D" chefs,
and they've sent us
these delicious recipes.
So on the final segment,
John Conley, our good buddy,
Fat Olives and Salsa Brava.
Your appreciation of
life, family,
the way you take
care of people,
it really represents
in the food that you make.
This is redunkulous.
So what's
the current status?
Everything's shut down.
I don't think I've ever
been to Fat Olives
and not seen
that oven cranking.
I know. This is the first time
it's been cold in eight years.
We've just been doing
research and development here
at Fat Olives.
My kids are coming in.
The tamale you're eating today
was developed by one of my kids.
It's going to go on the menu
at Salsa Brava.
Come on, Guy.
Ryder, he saw this.
Ryder wants to wear it.
So there you
go ahead, Ryder.
This is our
new cameraman look.
Let's see it, Ryder.
And this is
our cameraman.
Dun-dun-dun!
[ Laughter ]
Really?
You couldn't have
peeled the garlic?
Is that a whole onion?
A whole onion.
All right, so we've got
the tamales here,
and how long have
they got a steam?
They're going to take
about 5, 10 minutes
in the steamer.
They're already cooked,
so you just got to
bring them up
to temperature.
[ Bell dings ]
How are we looking,
John Conley?
Are they doing it?
We're looking good.
There we go.
Stacking them up
like we're really
doing tamales.
Nice.
John, next step?
What are we into?
We're going to make a classic
New Mexico red chili.
You have guajillo, and you have
dried New Mexico chilies.
Put that in boiling water
with four cloves of garlic
and half that onion.
Got it.
Hunter, you want to get
another little pot going.
We're going to do
a little amber rue.
There's some olive oil
and some flour there.
All right, so got good steam
on the tamales here.
By the way, you haven't even
told us what's in the tamale.
Yeah, so we have the white
corn masa, achiote,
rubbed chicken thigh,
Jack cheese.
Wait a second, there's a sign
dancing in the background.
Oh, this is Adam.
Adam is one of my faves.
He gets his
good looks from me.
FIERI:
And he's a wrestler.
I think you could wrestle
your dad to the ground.
He's afraid, actually.
[ Laughter ]
He's so scared.
"You got this, Flagstaff.
Stay strong."
Hey, Adam.
How you doing, brother?
You're going to take
those chilies, make your puree.
Chilies.
Yep.
Onions.
All of it.
Garlic.
Take some of
that nice stock.
It all goes in the bath.
Now pulverize it.
[ Blender whirring ]
You're going to run it
through the strainer
and get this cool
little puree.
Fold in a little bit
of that rue?
All the cumin,
and then salt to taste.
Now, how do you want
these served?
Put them right
in the center of a plate.
You'll open the tamale,
and you're going to put
that red chili
right across the top.
All right,
the moment of truth.
It's always that moment
when you're like, "Okay, wait."
Okay, he's going in.
Do you see that, Pete?
It's his third bite.
So, John, I'll tell you
this, buddy.
The right amount of chicken.
The masa is tender
but still firm.
This red chili sauce that's
going with it is excellent.
And I love the cheese.
Nice.
Mm.
I tell you, guys.
This is exactly
what we wanted it to be.
Creative.
You've done a fantastic job.
But we have to pick
a best dish.
Let me confer
with my team real quick.
All right, so congratulations.
A $500 donation will be made
in your name to R.E.R.F.
That's the
restaurantemployeerelieffund.us.
That will go to an employee
that is out of work
due to this pandemic.
Drum roll, please.
[ Drumming ]
Congratulations,
Scratch at Grinders!
[ Bell dinging, alarm blaring ]
Good job, Stretch.
Stretch, congrats!
Congratulations.
Nice sharp, guys.
That was awesome.
Nina, John, Panini, and Stretch,
thank you so much.
You have made this
a fantastic visit.
And there's plenty
more funky, crazy chefs
to show up
to this backyard.
We'll see you next week.
Take it easy.
All right, let's clean it up.
Good night.
That's a wrap.
There you go.
♪♪