Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Oh, oh, oh.
...we're digging
into some down home cooking.
That takes me back
to my childhood.
We've got a Southern treasure
in Oklahoma City.
I know you're the boss.
I like that.
[ Laughter ]
A hometown hero
in Garland, Utah...
This is way
off the beaten path,
but coming out here is
a special thing.
...and, in Denver...
So. good!
...comfort food [chuckle]
with a whole new spin.
Right here, on "Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives."
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
It's been about 12 years
since we first came to OKC
and we went to Leo's BBQ,
where he made
that strawberry cake
and he made the ribs.
You remember that?
Oh, that was good.
But I can't figure out
how I missed a joint
that's been doing it
for 67 years.
They've been doing
this country cooking
and they're getting known now
for something called
yam fried chicken.
Oh, that's right
up my alley.
This is Florence's Restaurant.
♪♪
Smothered pork chops.
There's no place like
Florence's in the Heartland.
I have chicken
& dumplings.
Country classic,
just like my grandmother
would've fixed,
back in the day,
when we were kids.
How'd you
find this place?
Man, this place has been
around since the '50s.
FIERI:
Which is when Florence Kemp
started cooking up
her brand
of Southern comfort here,
[chuckle]
at the age of 20.
And she's still
stirring the pot,
with the help
of her daughter Victoria.
How many generations of families
do you get coming through here?
We see fourth-generation
customers.
That's gotta make you
feel fantastic.
Yes.
I was born and raised
in the South
and, when I came here,
I knew I'd found the Mecca.
Fried rib appetizer.
The fried ribs are really
a unique kind of experience.
It's a light breading.
It's not too thick.
The barbecue sauce
is amazing.
What are we
gonna make today?
Fried ribs.
-Like pork ribs?
-Yes.
How'd you know
that's my middle name?
[ Laughter ]
-Guy Fried Ribs Fieri.
How do you
wanna start?
We cut these ribs.
So these are spare ribs,
or St. Louis-style ribs.
-Mm-hmm.
-Has this fried rib
always been on the menu?
-No. My dad used to live with me
and he got old
and I have to go home
and try to fix his dinner
and so this is something
I could fix quick.
He was 105.
Holy moly!
So we go from the
lemon juice and vinegar
into the water.
-Mm-hmm.
Now, this is gonna brine.
For a day?
Slow and steady is better.
Little longer,
the better.
So, when it
gets done...
We put the salt
and pepper on it.
Now, we're gonna make
the house-seasoned
par-fried ribs.
First, we start with flour.
This is the salt.
-Cornstarch.
-There we go.
Baking powder, pepper.
And then we put that
all over the ribs?
-Yes.
-Okay.
Then, we fry the rib
for 15 minutes.
How many come
with an order, Florence?
-Three or four.
-Who makes the laws around here?
Oh, my daughter thinks
that she's the mother now
and I'm the daughter.
[ Knock-knock ]
[ Laughs ]
Are we gonna serve these
with anything?
-Barbecue sauce.
-Okay.
I'm following the lead.
I know you're the boss.
I like that.
[ Laughter ]
Take this water
and pour it in the pot.
Okay, gonna put
the water in the pot.
Mm-hmm. And then,
we're gonna put all
of these dry ingredients.
The sugar. Looks like
a little onion powder.
-Mm-hmm.
-So a little barbecue spice.
Okay, a little cumin.
Little mustard.
Oh, we are a team.
Look at us go, Flo.
Oh, yeah.
Little liquid smoke.
Water or really
bad moonshine.
[laughing] It's vinegar.
Now, we'll go ketchup.
We'll let this cook down
and then,
when the ribs come out,
we'll get 'em
with the sauce.
Looking good.
♪♪
That's tasty.
Not too much batter.
Nice and juicy.
I think the key
was that
you soaked 'em
in the vinegar.
Got a nice little
flavor from that.
How do you like
that sauce?
Oh, there's good tang
in that sauce, ma'am.
Thank you.
I'm gonna have
more fried ribs.
[ Laughing ]
Fried rib appetizer.
Enjoy!
It's already a good rib,
but when you put that batter
on top of it,
it just takes it over the top.
Everybody should try
a fried rib, right?
Frying chicken right now,
in the hot grease.
You're a local food writer.
What is it about Florence's?
The world moves really fast,
but it doesn't here.
Florence is always here.
I mean, it's an inspiration
for how good you can get,
if you take the time
to do it that long.
When they ask,
"What do you want?"
I said, "I want
your yam fried chicken."
You've never tasted
something that is so moist,
so good, and so flavorful.
-What are we making now?
-Yam fried chicken.
I don't know what
yam fried chicken means,
so I'm just gonna follow ya.
-I'm gonna first take it
and season it
with salt and pepper.
And then, we also have
a little seasoning
in the flour, too.
-Mm-hmm.
How old are those Dutch
ovens, there, Florence?
Oh, I wore out
about five or six of 'em.
I don't think I've ever
heard of anybody
wearing out
a Dutch oven.
I think you probably
wore out
some people
that have worked here.
I think there've been people
that come to work here
and that have had
to go retire
and you're still working?
Yes. And they ask me
all the time
when I'm gonna retire.
I don't think that's
gonna happen.
Not soon, I hope.
Some of the people
that work here told me
that, once in a while,
you quit.
I get mad, I'll just,
"I don't work anymore."
[ Laughs ]
-And where do you go?
-Nowhere. [laughs]
-Oh, I gotta try that.
I quit.
We're gonna make
candied yams out of these.
Bunch of cooked yams.
Put all of this sugar
in there.
That's a lotta
sugar, ma'am.
You're in for a treat.
Add some butter.
After a while,
it'll turn into syrup.
Anything else we're
gonna serve with this?
-We add greens.
-Collard greens?
Yes. I'm gonna put these
in the pot
and then I'll pour all
of this water in.
Baking soda.
There's the sugar, salt.
-Chicken stock?
-Put all of that stock in.
They're gonna cook
about an hour and a half.
Plain old fried
chicken's good for me,
but now I'm going
yam fried chicken.
We've already put our yams
on the plate.
-Okay.
-Take the collard greens.
Okay, good.
Right in the sauce you go.
Now, you try that.
Alright.
♪♪
You invented that?
-Yes.
-Delicious.
You really seasoned
your chicken well.
There's a lotta flavor
in that pot.
I love collard greens.
Nice and tender.
Not mushy.
Perfectly cooked chicken,
tender candied yams,
and you --
package deal.
Fantastic.
I need that
yam fried chicken.
Amazing. Tender and juicy
on the inside.
The yam sauce just made it
so delicious.
And how
about the collards?
I have 'em every time
I come here
and I come here from two
to three times a week.
Fried chicken.
I needed it 15 minutes ago.
I'm running behind.
So, you know, Casey,
this is a must go-to.
-Absolutely.
-You have to try it.
All your taste buds are just
gonna come alive at one time.
You're a big personality.
You walk softly
and carry a big stick.
Yes, I do.
-"Yes, I do."
-[Laughing]
I resemble that remark.
Thank you very much
for having me.
I really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Watch out
for Florence.
She'll quit.
She'll be back.
♪♪
Up next,
another local landmark.
The story don't stop.
-It doesn't.
This time, a century-old spot
in Garland, Utah...
This is a center
of the community.
...serving up some
old-school favorites...
It's delicious.
It makes me smile.
...with some sweet on the side.
That's the most
doughnut/maple bar
I've eaten
on "Triple D," ever.
♪♪
So I'm here in Garland, Utah,
population 2,400,
and I'm about 80 miles
from Salt Lake City.
Now, you're saying to yourself,
"Guy, why are you and 'Triple D'
out there to check out
one restaurant?"
I'll tell you exactly why.
The place opened in 1922.
They're known for their pies.
They're known
for their doughnuts
and they're known
for their rolls and gravy.
And they've been doing
old-school the entire time.
Ladies and gentlemen, there are
not a lot of these places left.
I had to check it out.
This is The Pie Dump.
♪♪
We got a rib eye
and fry
and a cinnamon roll
for Table 2.
The Pie Dump has been here
almost 100 years.
Still has that old
hometown feeling.
Rolls are looking good.
You know, it's home cooking,
just like your mom used to make.
This is fantastic.
FIERI:
And so is the story here.
The latest owners
of this old-school joint
are Mac and Cherie Munns,
but, after decades in the biz,
they're handing off the next era
to employee Maggie Fitzgerald.
-[Laughing]
-When did you two
come into play?
1975, I went to work
next door cutting meat
and I'd come over
and serve the kids.
Then you bought
The Pie Dump?
-Yep.
-You're...
-Managing.
-And you're gonna take over?
-Yep.
-That's awesome.
We got a French dip
and fry for Table 3.
French dip is one
of the specialties here.
It's got really
tender roast beef on it
and the bread is
to die for.
Today we're gonna make
sourdough bread.
This is for doughnuts,
hot rolls.
This is the
foundation dough
of the whole thing here.
We're gonna start off
with hot water,
oil, dough softener.
Don't ask me what it is.
It just works.
Don't ask him what it is.
Sugar and salt.
It's not a speed round,
just so you know.
Eggs.
And our sourdough starter,
over 50 years old.
Flour.
1/2 pound of yeast.
Mix it up.
12 minutes.
Then we're gonna let it
rest and proof?
Yep.
We're gonna make hoagie buns
for the French dips.
He moves fast, folks.
Stick with him.
You don't drive
this fast, do you?
75, stay alive.
Plenty of flour,
so it don't stick.
Where did the
Jack LaLanne workout
wheel come from?
I had a friend of mine
make it.
This is how fast
everything goes
around here?
This is slow because they're
sticking together.
Put them in the proofer.
-We let it proof how long?
Just like wine --
'til it's ready.
Bake no bread
until its time.
Oh, you stop it.
We'll bake 'em up
at what temp?
About 325 on the convection.
Alright.
So, now, I've got you.
So let's get
into the French dip.
We're gonna start
by seasoning our beef flat.
First, we want salt.
We put a lot.
I can see that.
Pepper, garlic powder.
Put fat-side-up.
Okay.
Add some more garlic powder.
Pepper.
-And the salt.
-And that's it.
Okay. We're gonna go
in the oven?
For one hour.
Take it out and put
1.5 gallons of water.
-Okay.
Then cover it and then turn it
down for three more hours.
Alright, let's see it.
So a little trim,
just taking
the fat off it.
Alright, throw it on.
You always wanna do it
where you're
against the grain.
Now, you can get this
as a dinner also?
Yeah, and it'd just be
a thicker cut.
Okay. You're so humble
and so nice.
You seem like you're
part of their family.
And then,
you're gonna get ready
to take over a legend.
You gonna change anything
when you take over?
Not for a while.
Just add different things
to the menu.
-You want more work?!
-[Chuckle]
What else
do we have to do?
Now, we're gonna make
our fry sauce.
-Let's see it.
-So we take
Miracle Whip mayonnaise,
ketchup,
and mustard.
-And that's fry sauce?
-Yep.
It's fresh made.
I have to try it
right now.
♪♪
That's good.
I like that.
It's a little bit sweeter.
The Miracle Whip
is what does that.
Let's make
the French dip.
Okay.
We weigh out 4 ounces.
And where did
our jus come from?
-All the drippings.
-Last, but not least.
Cheese, if we want it.
Then, cut it in half.
Okay.
♪♪
That's exactly
what I wanted
as a French dip
when I was a kid.
I want hot roast beef,
a little bit of cheese,
a really good roll,
and some au jus
that you wanna drink
just like a soup,
and that's exactly
what this is.
It's delicious.
It makes me smile.
Just right out of the
old-school recipe book,
served
in a kitchen that
been serving it
for...
Almost 100 years.
The year that I buy it,
it'll be 100 years.
We'll have a party.
You could come.
-I can?
-[laughing] Yeah.
You could come
to any party I have.
[ Laughter ]
French dip here.
The roast beef is
really tender and moist
and the dipping sauce is
really out of this world.
Just simple, you know?
That's what I love about it.
This whole place
is just old hometowny.
FIERI:
And the spot for generations
of schoolkids next door.
Kids'll skip
out of lunch break
to go to The Pie Dump,
even though they're not
supposed to.
It's just that good.
How long you been
coming here?
Probably since
the mid-'70s.
We'd sneak over here
in the morning
and get a hot roll
and a bowl of gravy
before we went to school.
You'd get a who, where,
and a what, what?
Hot roll
and a bowl of gravy.
[chuckling] Also known
as the rip and dip.
It's like a hot roll
straight from the oven
with butter on it,
and then it has the gravy.
-Rip it and dip it.
-So kids would come in
and just order this?
-Oh, all the time.
-And adults.
We would roll 400
to 600 rolls a day.
This is ridiculous.
And coming up...
another Pie Dump tradition!
I got two maple bars
for that order, folks.
The maple bar
is amazing.
-There's nothing quite like it.
-When we come back.
♪♪
Okay, we're gonna do it
on this one.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
When you meet up with a friend
in Garland, Utah,
chances are,
it's at The Pie Dump.
The Pie Dump
is a historic marker
in the Garland,
Utah, area.
It's been here so long,
it's kinda integrated
into the community.
Every Saturday morning,
we'll come here
and have breakfast
and we'll get doughnuts.
I got two maple bars ready
to go for ya, folks!
The maple bar's something
I've always grown up with.
Great way
to start your morning.
-This is the maple bar?
-Yep.
It's the same dough,
but it's cut
at a different size?
-Yep.
-Okay.
Why are these going
on a wire rack
for proofing?
We're gonna deep dry 'em
in the fryer
right here
after they're proofed.
The whole rack goes
in the fryer?
-Yep.
-Who taught you that one?
-Come up with it myself.
-Okay, MacGyver.
I'm gonna put these in the
proofer and then I'm done.
Maggie's gonna take over
and finish up these maple bars.
Bring on Maggie.
Oh, those are ready to go.
-Oh, yeah.
-So just let it submerge
right down into it?
-Yep.
-How long will these go?
Like about 3 minutes,
or until they're golden brown.
And you gotta put
that lid down on 'em,
-Yeah.
-otherwise they will --
[chuckling]
Oh, oh, oh.
There you go.
Alright.
Now, we have to make
the maple bar topping.
Powdered sugar.
We make all of our frostings.
How many frostings
do you make?
White for the cinnamon rolls,
glazed, chocolate, maple.
You're a machine.
A little butter?
Yep. It's like
alternative butter.
And then maple and vanilla.
Together again
for the first time.
And the water.
And put the whisk on
and you just let it stir up.
-Doughnuts ready to come out?
-Yeah.
So many things going on,
I'm getting confused.
As a kid, the maple bar,
growing up in the little
town of Ferndale,
Sven used to make it
at the Ferndale bakery
and this was
the only doughnut
that I ever liked.
So we take
the frosting.
We have the dried
breadcrumbs
that go on top?
-Yep, and they have
cinnamon in 'em.
Cinnamon
and breadcrumbs,
to put that extra
little crunch on top.
-There!
-What was that little scream
you just gave?
Kind of excited
about that. I don't
know what that was.
Waarrhh!
-[Laughs]
♪♪
Mmm! Little breadcrumb
thing on top's the bomb.
That takes me back
to my childhood.
That's awesome.
I don't think I've
ever had one warm.
-Mmm!
-People even ask us
to put 'em in the microwave
and then it melts it
on top again.
You hold a record.
That's the most
doughnut/maple bar
I've eaten
on "Triple D," ever.
And it's fantastic.
We've got hot doughnuts
ready to go, folks.
The maple bar is
really good.
Just the right amount
of sweetness.
It's not too sweet.
I think the cinnamon
kinda calms it down.
Yeah, it's always the
cinnamon-amon-amon-amon.
So you get the softness
of the bread
and then you get some of that
creaminess from the frosting.
This is usually
what I get here.
Has it been made the same
since you were a kid?
-Yeah.
-See, that's what I like,
is that they haven't
changed things.
The fact this place
has been here this long,
a lotta people working
really hard
to make it happen.
You guys are really lucky.
-Yeah.
We got a chicken
cordon bleu and fry,
and rip and dip
ready to go.
MAN:
Wanna feel good about life,
you come to The Pie Dump.
I can't imagine the
community without it.
This is way
off the beaten path,
but coming out here is
a special thing.
This is a center
of the community
and your history
and all the hard work
and love and energy
that you put into it
is gonna get carried on.
I mean, this is --
That'll make you cry.
[ Chuckle ]
What do you do
when you retire?
My son and I
haul sod together.
He hired me to drive one
of his trucks.
[ Horn toots ]
I'm following 20 grandkids
wherever I want to.
-The story don't stop.
-It does not.
Coming up...
a funky spot in Denver...
That's pretty outrageous.
...adding a dash of healthy...
All thriller, no filler.
...to hearty classics.
Bro, this is spot on.
♪♪
Now, we first started
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
way back in the day.
I said, "You know what?
We'll be able to do this
for a couple years
and then,
we'll run out of places."
Well, we know that's not
the truth, right?
We just continue to find
these amazing joints
all over the country.
You know what I love
to see right now?
I love to see that the
restaurants are adapting
and growing to serving
the needs of the guests.
They want paleo.
They want gluten-free, nut-fee.
They want keto,
so, when you find a restaurant
that's doing all of that,
and then some,
here in Denver, Colorado,
I gotta check it out.
This is Just Be Kitchen.
Garnishing with kale
chips right now.
Absolutely love the food here.
It's just amazing.
[singsong]
Breakfast burrito.
Just Be is completely different
from any other restaurant.
FIERI:
That's 'cause owner
Jennifer Peters
and Chef Chase Elliot aren't
known for what they serve,
but, rather,
what they don't serve.
Gluten-free,
sugar-free.
-Dairy-free.
-Grain-free.
Soy-, corn-, peanut-,
legume-free.
Right here, on "Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives."
[ Laughing ]
Everybody thinks
that healthy food has
to be about kale
and quinoa salads.
We wanted to like create
craveable foods
that are
about fulfillment.
Jen will take staples
from things you grew up with
and, yeah, she can make
healthy versions of that,
but, still tasting really good.
Cozy chicken
& dumplings!
The chicken & dumplings,
it's got the chicken.
It's got the vegetables.
It's got the carrots.
It's this
rich medley of flavor.
Starting off,
we're making our broth
for the chicken & dumplings.
-Okay.
We got
our chicken feet here
and add a little bit of salt
and then we'll roast them off.
Hang on,
let me think.
It's good for scratching,
too, if you need it.
-Oh, I see what you're saying.
-Yeah. Uh-huh.
We're gonna dump this
into the pot with some water.
That's gonna go
for about 24 hours.
-Got it.
-We've got coconut
shortening here
for our
chicken & dumpling gravy.
Cassava flour.
Hungarian paprika.
Salt!
Some garlic powder here.
Onion powder.
-Got it.
-And our chicken broth.
It's gonna have to boil
to get its consistency.
Okay.
Dumpling time.
Coconut shortening here.
A high-fat
coconut milk.
People used to come
and ask me
all the time,
in my restaurant,
if there was anything
fat-free, and I said,
"All the fat's free."
[ Laughter ]
Apple cider vinegar,
salt, baking powder,
xanthan gum.
And the xanthan gum
is the binder?
That's gonna hold it
all together.
And then we add
our cassava flour.
When did it turn
into dry ice?
It goes everywhere.
Enjoy. [laughs]
And then, we're gonna
scoop our dough.
Bake it off at 350 degrees
for about 20 minutes.
This is
our end result.
Yes, sir.
Make it happen,
Cap'n.
Cooked chicken.
Roasted carrots.
This is gonna go right
on our flat top here.
Throw a little bit
of water on there.
Cover that for just a second.
We're gonna
take our mug here.
I've never seen chicken
& dumplings like this.
Our stock here.
Scallion, cilantro.
There we go.
This is gonna be hot.
♪♪
Let's just get
away from the whole,
"It's gluten-free.
It's healthy, dah, dah, dah."
This is legit
chicken & dumplings.
♪♪
The gravy's light.
It's rich,
got a lotta flavor.
It's got a lotta body.
Nice little crunch in the veg.
Bro, this is spot on.
I'll have it by the quart,
thank you.
-[Laughs]
Chicken & dumplings
in the window.
Take it up.
You can taste
the savory chicken
and then there's
a nice texture change
when you get
the dumpling.
They're kind of doughy,
but they're still crispy
on the outside.
Hey, guys!
I've got the Passion
vegetable curry.
I love coming
to Just Be Kitchen.
It's my favorite
restaurant.
-And the name?
-Well, I'm single.
At the time,
I was single.
Oh. I was just putting
out the big ad!
I'm still single.
[laughing]
-Come on down.
-Accepting applications.
And there's a quote
on the wall that says,
"How do you find the one?
Be the one."
So, Just Be Kitchen.
With everything that's
on the walls,
no matter what type
of mood you're in, coming in,
you're gonna leave
in a great mood
and you're gonna be
definitely fulfilled.
Wholehearted
pork green chili
with a side tortilla.
The green chili
is excellent.
It is filled
with chunks of pork
that's just so savory.
We have no fillers
in our green chili.
This is straight-up --
-All thriller, no filler.
That's right.
We're starting
with our washed
and shucked tomatillos,
red onions,
some jalapeños, limes.
Talk about
10 pounds of stuff
in a 5-pound bag
right now.
Exactly.
Garlic, olive oil,
salt, cumin.
Coriander's gonna
finish this off.
-In the oven.
-350 for about an hour,
hour and a half.
-And then grind this up?
-Right. Yep.
-Okay.
So we're gonna take the pork
and throw that right in here.
We're gonna add
tomatillo mix,
bone broth,
salt, got some cumin,
coriander.
And how long we gonna
let this cook down?
-30 minutes or so.
-Dig it.
So we're gonna be making
our cheddar Whiz.
-Let's see it.
-Cauliflower, carrots, squash.
Boil that
for about 30, 45 minutes.
-Okay.
-Coconut milk in.
Mustard powder,
salt, onion powder,
garlic powder,
nutritional yeast.
Alright, let's hit it.
We're almost done.
Take us to the
vegan neighborhood
of Flavor Town.
Gonna make our tortillas.
Tapioca starch,
almond flour, water.
That'll go
for about 5 minutes.
Ball it up, flatten it,
roll it out.
We're gonna throw that
right on here.
While that's finishing up,
this is our final
pork-green chili product.
Cheddar Whiz,
the scallions,
cilantro,
and the jalapeños.
And you are ready
to go, sir.
♪♪
Wow. Tons of flavor.
So creamy.
The highlight
of this whole meal
is the tortilla that tears
and looks like that.
You'd be pretty hard pressed
to tell somebody
that's not a flour tortilla.
Exactly.
That's pretty outrageous.
So. good!
Wholehearted
pork green chilies
in the window.
The pork is amazing.
The broth is really hearty.
It has a little bit
of a kick to it.
The tortilla is the best
tortilla I've ever eaten.
I have a couple
of autoimmune diseases.
I couldn't eat out anywhere.
-Exactly.
So, when Just Be Kitchen
came around,
it was really, really special.
Biscuits & gravy.
So we're not going
for "Good, for gluten-free."
We're going for just "Good."
That's such the attitude,
my friend. Well done.
-Cheers.
-Watch out for this guy.
So, was this a great
road trip, or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next time,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Please do share.
-Okay. You gotta rip.
-Uh-huh.
-And dip.
-Shake and bake.
-Yeah.
I should've got up early
for this group.
This table's on fire.
[ Laughter ]