So when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks,
I got to be --
Dad, can we just,
I mean, please,
go to a restaurant
at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them send us dinner?
Huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got righteous pasta
coming from our buddy
Tony at Rino's in Boston.
He's setting the bar
really high.
Eric at Momocho's in Cleveland
is cooking up
some crazy enchiladas.
You're transported,
no passport necessary.
We're getting real-deal,
Neapolitan pizza
from a real-deal Italian chef,
Roberto, at Don Antonio's.
It's delicious.
And for dessert,
our sister Trina
at Se7enbites in Orlando,
well, she's sending
a funnel cake apple pie.
We're going to pop.
I just want you to know that.
And on top of it all, they're
going to video conference in
to give us
the true "Triple-D" experience.
I like
the way you think.
Exactly.
This is "Triple-D" Takeout.
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Hey, you guys, how are you?
-Hello.
-How are you, buddy?
Hunter, Ryder, and Guy here,
hanging out at the Fieri house.
Let me introduce you
to some of my favorite chefs
from "Triple-D"
doing a little takeout.
We've got Tony from Rino's
in Boston.
We've got Eric from Momocho's
all the way in Cleveland.
We've got Trin from Se7enbites
in Orlando, and we got...
What's that guy's
name down there?
I can't think
of his name.
Oh, Chef Roberto from
Don Antonio's in New York City.
We can't make it back
all the time
to go check out
our favorite "Triple-D" joints.
So we figured we would
just call you up,
politely request
to package up
one of your new
signature dishes,
and send it our way.
Here we go.
Ryder's running the cameras.
Hunter is
the fantastic sous chef.
And who's up first?
Chef Tony?
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
Chef Tony.
Alright.
While Hunter unpacks this,
give me a little rundown.
What's new in the world
of Rino's besides everybody
still has to wait an hour
and a half to get in?
Can't complain. You know?
It's been 150 times
that I've called you.
"Hey, listen,
I got a cousin in town.
Hey, listen, I got a buddy
that's coming."
And then
we get them in.
Yeah, you always get them in.
No problem.
But I'm not kidding you,
if you want to come here,
you got to go get ready
to wait in line.
It's the tiniest, little,
busiest kitchen I've ever seen.
Pick up.
GUY: I know that you're known
for making great pasta
fresh for service.
There should be music
to this right now.
This should be a video.
There you go.
You're following
all the principles but one.
What's that?
Ridiculous portion.
Oh, portions.
Let me show you.
Normal.
Normal. Yes.
Tony, I'm not kidding.
Easily two pounds of food.
Dude,
I'm beyond impressed.
Thank you.
This is hilarious.
He sent a pan.
Why not?
That way you can use that one.
That's all.
I think I'm in trouble.
I didn't send a pan.
Why are you trying to make
the rest of us look bad, Tony?
And a plate.
I sent you the dish
to plate it up with, alright?
Napkins?
I guess so. I don't know.
My wife packed it.
Tablecloth. What is the dish
that you sent us, Ton?
We're making pasta al forno
with pappardelle.
So I got sheeted pasta.
I've got fresh pasta
that needs to be sheeted.
And I also have...
Pappardelle already made.
Pappardelle ready to go.
There you go.
Let me just tell you other
three, you better be ready.
Okay?
He set the bar really high.
Alright.
So let's get into this.
Let's get
the meatball going.
In a bowl,
add all three ground meats.
The veal, the beef,
the pork.
Add salt and pepper.
The Parmesan cheese?
The Parmesan cheese.
Yes.
Okay. Next?
Parsley.
I got the parsley.
Oregano.
How many breadcrumbs?
I'll tell you when to stop.
Go.
That's good.
Add some extra virgin
olive oil.
This is just Tony.
He's just ranting.
Okay. That's good.
How many eggs you want in, Tony?
Two?
Two, please.
We're going to mix
these meatballs.
What size do you want them,
Ton?
Like a quarter.
Hold, please.
Turn.
Your thumb's on the wrong side.
I can't. My arm doesn't
twist that way.
Then do it the right way.
My pinkie is all bent.
This is like putting ski boots
on your kids
when they're toddlers.
You know what I'm saying?
Alright. How are we going
to cook these meatballs?
Just cook them in a pan
with some
extra virgin olive oil
that I sent you.
That's lot of meatballs
right there.
DICENSO:
Once the meatballs are fried,
you're going to add
the meatballs to the sauce.
Tony,
what's in the tomato sauce?
A little bit of garlic,
these beautiful Roma tomatoes.
Fresh basil,
salt and pepper.
That's it.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Got it.
So you send me
this beautiful pappardelle.
Run me through
the recipe.
Flour, eggs,
a little bit of salt,
a little bit
of extra virgin olive oil.
Bind it all together,
and that's it.
That enough pasta,
Tony?
Yeah, that's fine.
You sent me enough
for two orders.
Oh, that looks
so delicious.
Add the ricotta
to the sauce.
Okay.
The shredded mozzarella, yeah.
There you go, Hunter.
You're doing a great job.
Thank you.
I'll be here all week.
Once the pasta's done,
add the rest
of the mozzarella cheese on top,
and then bake it in the oven.
In the pan?
In the pan, yes.
And then
from the pan,
we'll slide it off
into the bowl.
Slide it off the dish
if you can handle it.
[ Laughter ]
Talk a big game.
Tony.
Come on,
you know I love you.
Trin,
when he comes to Orlando,
he's definitely not getting
any kind of love at Chicken Guy,
and you're not going to
let him in Se7en. Okay?
Okay.
Pasta looks beautiful.
Mozzarella cheese on top
and pop it in the oven.
That's what it takes?
Exactly. It's easy.
This is Rino's
in California.
Tell him to --
We'll throw it in the oven.
What?
Keep talking, Tony.
We're going to go to commercial,
and you just keep talking.
Have a good time.
We'll throw it the oven.
See you on "Triple-D" Takeout
in a bit.
Go ahead.
He's still talking.
Are they going in
the pizza oven?
Come here.
More cheese.
What are you doing?
Take a look at that.
Welcome back.
"Triple-D" Takeout.
We've got Eric from Momocho's
in Cleveland,
the one and only Chef Roberto
from Kesté in New York City,
Trin from Se7enbites
in Orlando,
and Tony from Rino's
in Boston
sent us beautiful ingredients
to make a la minute...
Pasta al forno
with pappardelle.
Looks amazing.
I know everybody at home
is looking at this, going,
"This is ridiculous.
There's no way that
that's the size portion
that he makes."
But that is the size portion
that Tony makes.
Fresh-made pasta,
hand-rolled meatballs.
Beautiful filetto
tomato sauce,
screaming hot out
of the wood-fired oven.
HUNTER: Are you really going to
do that? That's hot.
Careful, careful.
[ Mumbles indistinctly ]
Hot.
He did the hot dance.
Why do you do that to yourself?
Just wait a second.
I'm hungry.
The key to that meatball
is without question that veal.
Would you get your big old
elbows out of here?
I'm trying to eat.
That looks delicious.
Mmm.
If you're going to enjoy pasta
in today's no-carb world --
I know Tony doesn't follow
that -- this is how you do it.
I can't believe that Ryder's
not over here yet.
MAN: Here he comes.
The mozzarella on top
is key.
Parmesan inside
the meatball is right on.
The ricotta
into the sauce
just takes it to another nice,
creamy level.
It is delicious,
and the pasta is nice firm.
Bro, outstanding.
Nice job, Tony.
While we continue to sit here
and inhale this,
our buddy Eric from Momocho's
in Cleveland
made some of the craziest
guacamole I've ever seen.
And I'm a guacamole guy.
The one we're making today,
smoked trout and bacon.
Whoa.
That's great, man.
I'd write a book
about guacamole if I was you,
and just put that in there.
Just one page.
Open it up.
There you go.
I can tell which one is yours.
It's spray-painted.
I love spray paint,
and I love stickers.
What is this?
A local artist in Cleveland
made us a Guy screen.
Two copies
in the whole world.
One is in your hand and one
is right next to me at Momocho.
The big, bad flavor daddy.
Dude, I want
to remind everybody,
we do pick
a best dish in this.
Now, that will involve
no cash or prizes,
simply just
bragging rights.
But this right now
is a good start.
Eric, you're taking
a very strong formidable lead.
Let's talk about
what we're making.
Enmolada is a classic Mexican
dish that focuses on a mole.
Alright, so I got a hot pan.
What am I doing here?
The way we serve our enmoladas
is with lamb, slow-braised,
with some citrus, some herbs,
and some avocado leaves.
If the lamb is that good cold,
help us.
Some of the lamb jus
into the shredded lamb?
-Yep.
-I wish we had smell-o-vision.
What's in the mole?
The number-one ingredient
is time.
Mole takes a good
two days to make.
We have corn tortilla,
flour tortilla,
four different types
of dried chilies,
tomatoes, raisins,
tomatillo,
bananas, three different types
of powdered chilies,
white sugar,
cumin, coriander,
Mexican chocolate,
salt, pepper.
It's a half-hour show,
bud.
Corn tortillas
or flour tortillas?
Let's go with corn.
Dip them in some oil
for like two seconds.
And I would do three or four.
Well, I got got to let
Ryder and Hunter eat.
6 to 10, then.
Put meat in the middle
of each one of those tortillas.
Smells amazing.
Douse that plate with
red chili and chocolate mole.
Right across the top,
a strip of peanuts,
a couple of
the pickled shallots.
Did I send you a little
triangle wedge of Cotija?
You did. Right here.
Now, Roberto and Tony,
Cotija is like
the Mexican Parmesan.
Take notes.
No comment.
Cilantro?
Yep.
And you're good to go.
By just using the lamb neck,
I can't believe how great
that's going to taste.
♪♪
I got to tell you,
Chef.
Thinking about eating
Mexican food in Cleveland
didn't just jump out
at me and say,
"Wow, this is going
to be awesome."
But once you get to the
doorsteps of Momocho Mod Mex,
this is
what you're in for.
You're transported,
no passport necessary.
This is real deal, bro.
If I would've called you
the Guacamole King,
I would have to
dethrone you from that
and now call you
the Mole Master.
Hey, Hunter, remember that
last thing in the box?
No, he's going to try to eat it
on a flip-flop.
That's how good it is.
Come on.
I'll tell you what,
buddy.
That's too good to be eaten
on a flip-flop.
How do you like that?
Huh?
Appreciate it.
Listen, folks, hanging out
at the Fieri house.
When we come back,
two more big-time
surprises you're going to love.
We'll see you in a bit.
This is mine.
It's not yours.
Here. You put the --
You get your own.
Try on the flip-flops.
Get away from me.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple-D" Takeout.
Hanging out at the Fieri house
here in Northern California.
We have invited
four of our favorite
"Triple-D" chefs to, well,
send us takeout.
We're talking Momocho's
out of Cleveland.
We're talking Rino's
out of Boston,
the Se7enbites
out of Orlando.
And up next,
out of New York City,
the one and only
Chef Roberto.
How are you?
So he has Don Antonio's.
Okay?
Well, I've met Don Antonio
when I went to Naples,
so that's where
the Neapolitan pizza
comes over
to the United States
and where Chef Roberto partners
up for Don Antonio's.
What makes true
Neapolitan pizza?
The most important
start from the dough.
Table?
Table very, very -- No.
Okay.
No, no.
No throw.
Antonio tell you,
you touch your dough
like how you
touch your wife.
Hang on a second. I'm going
to make a note of that one.
But now he's got another place,
Kesté.
It's a pizza school,
and he teaches you
how to make
Neapolitan-style pizza.
And we start to ship all over
the country, the pizza go.
You can call us, and we can ship
overnight the pizza to you.
I love it. I hope you sent me
something exciting.
Hunter?
♪♪
Smoked mozzarella. Nice.
We have truffle
and burrata.
Prosciutto, porchetta.
This is
a 10-topping pizza.
Evidently, it is.
There's a surprise
in here.
That is something for Guy.
I'm going to just tell you
right now,
if it's what I think it is,
and it's --
Thanks for tuning in, folks.
Show's over.
Oh, my gosh.
Look at that.
-Whoa.
-Wow.
Nice.
You tell me that's not doing it
for you right there.
That's amazing.
-Cheater.
-Yeah, cheater is exactly right.
Okay, Chef,
what are we making
with the 90,000 ingredients
that you sent?
Pizza with burrata.
You take the dough.
That's got a little
whole wheat in it.
Yeah. You remember I told you
be gentle,
the way
you touch your wife.
Tell me what
we're putting on it.
You cover
all pizza on basil.
All the pizza is in basil?
More.
We're trying to put as more
as we can, Chef.
Now put the cherry tomato
on top.
Is the porchetta
going on this, Chef?
No, on the next pizza.
On the next pizza?
Yes.
How many pizzas
are we making?
I thought this was
a one dish.
Yes, so now
you pick up burrata.
With all the truffle
in it that you make.
All the truffle inside.
Yes.
Black or white truffles?
CAPORUSCIO: There are black
and white truffles together.
Oh, that sounds delicious.
It smells fantastic.
Okay. In the oven?
90 seconds.
Ryder, follow me.
90 seconds
at about 800 degrees?
Yes.
Alright.
How's that look, Chef?
Very good.
Cut it first?
And after,
put on top the prosciutto.
I love prosciutto.
-Oh.
-Just give me a piece.
Here you go.
Boy,
that is so delicious.
You got some prosciutto
on your chin there, Guy.
Do I?
It's for later.
No, that's my goatee.
Now can we finally eat it?
Yes.
♪♪
So just as I was saying
with Momocho's, or with Rino's,
when you get
these simple ingredients
that you treat the right way,
you just don't overdo it.
A good amount of basil
protecting the dough
from the tomatoes, hitting on
that fresh burrata with truffle.
And then when it's all done,
you go ahead
and just lay on some of
that beautiful aged prosciutto.
I got to tell you,
Chef.
One of the more simple pizzas.
I think people would see it.
They'd go,
"Come on,
burrata and prosciutto?
Is it that big of a deal?
Really?
We're going to make
all this noise about it?"
I will tell you what, it's all
this noise and then some.
Delicious.
Thank you.
And we've got another pizza
to make.
Here we have
a gluten-free dough
that has to be handled
a little bit more delicately.
This dough is made with
rice starch, cornstarch,
and they take off the gluten
from the wheat.
So it's wheat inside
but no gluten.
Smoked mozzarella?
Smoked mozzarella
and basil on top.
Very good, Hunter.
Alright.
Now the porchetta?
Yeah.
Now the porchetta.
Put how much you like.
You can cover up porchetta.
I can't handle any more
of this today.
Into the oven?
In the oven now, yes.
Very close to the mouth.
Don't put it
in the back.
Put it close
to the front of the mouth.
So we got 90 seconds.
The pizza is cooking.
We got to
go to commercial.
We have to clean up
this hot mess.
Hey, Hunter, where were you?
See you in a bit.
Sorry, folks.
Park's closed.
Welcome back.
"Triple-D" Takeout
here at the Fieri house,
and we've got some
of our favorite chefs
from around the country
sending all kinds
of delicious ingredients
for us to semi-prepare
ourselves.
We've got Tony
from Rino's,
Eric from Momocho's,
Trin from Se7enbites.
And here we have Chef Roberto
from Don Antonio's
and Kesté
in New York City.
We already had a pizza,
and we got another pizza
to make.
Smoked mozzarella,
porchetta.
It looks amazing,
Roberto.
I cannot wait to come
to New York and visit you.
I'll ship over to you.
That's what
I'm talking about.
That is one hot pie.
You have a lemon now.
Always finish
with a little zest.
We have
the gluten-free crust.
Look at how that crust
holds itself up.
It is screaming hot
right now.
Dad, I don't understand.
Do you have magic fingers?
[ Laughter ]
There you go.
[ Mumbles indistinctly ]
The hotter, the better.
There's been so many
gluten-free doughs
that I've had
that are so chalky
and don't have the texture
and don't have the bite
and don't have the chew,
that thing you love about pizza.
This is
every bit pizza dough.
Matter of fact,
if you didn't tell somebody
that this was
gluten-free,
I don't think anybody would
question you about it.
Not just the Fieris, but
everybody can reach out to you,
and you'll send them
this gluten-free dough.
Correct?
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Delicious pizzas simply made,
quality ingredients,
correct preparation and style.
Fantastic.
I wore my Chicken Guy
shirt today
because I have my Chicken Guy
restaurant there in Orlando.
And when I think about Orlando,
I think of one and only.
Is she drinking wine
right in the middle of this?
I love little
Se7enbites.
Alright, Trin,
you're going to wrap out
this whole entire circus.
Hunter, go get the box.
GREGORY-PROPST:
I sent all kinds of treats
in the top of that box.
When we did the chicken
pot pie at your place,
I have to still tell you,
it is one of my favorites.
Chicken pot pie is kind of
like kryptonite for me.
Oh.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
That is legit.
There you go.
I kind of need you to have
your bandana on.
I'm rolling this
for sure.
Alright. Alright.
Let's go.
This is all kinds of goodies
in here.
Wait a second.
That is
the Don't Fudge With Me bar.
Bite it.
Put it in your mouth.
But no, we're going to see
if we can get
Lori to come over here
and try this.
There we go.
This one right here
might take the cake.
Oh, I know what this is.
-Yes, you do.
-I know what this is.
That's for Ryder.
Vanilla bean bourbon-bacon
moon pies.
Ryder, this is all for you,
buddy.
Wow.
Nice job.
Look at Ryder
getting the shot in there.
These are ridiculous.
And people can have
this FedEx'd to them?
-We can.
-That looks delicious.
You better ship
to Cleveland.
That was killer.
Wow.
Alright.
Tell us what's happening
in the great world
of Se7en.
A lot of things are really
happening right now.
We're expanding our menu.
And what you're about to make
is one of the things
that we're adding.
Fair-favorite funnel cake meets
apple pie -- all Americana.
And I made some homemade
cinnamon ice cream
to go on top of it.
We're going to pop.
I just want you to know that.
Alright.
How do we start this?
You got a whip up
that funnel cake batter.
Flour, funnel cake,
vanilla milk.
The two of those together
and the eggs?
Yes. And then there should
also be some cardamom,
salt, and baking powder.
I see the vanilla seeds
that just went in there.
And you're going to whisk
that all together.
Take out your tortillas, and
you're going to lay those flat.
You're going to use that
around the whole outer edge.
That's going to be
kind of your glue
that's going to hold your little
funnel cake burrito together.
Got it.
And then I made you some of
our standard apple pie filling.
And you're going to put
about two spoonfuls
in the center of that.
Wow. That is caramel-y.
What is in this?
Granny Smith apples,
cinnamon.
It's got some of our
finished caramel in it.
And then you're going to wrap it
up like a tight little package.
Roll it around in
that funnel cake batter.
Okay.
And then
you're going to drop it
right into your
370-degree hot oil.
We'll see
if it holds together.
Good job.
Hey, Hunter.
Yes, that's perfect.
And then you're going to get
that cinnamon ice cream
and your chipotle caramel sauce
ready to top that bad boy.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
who made the ice cream?
I did.
Where are you going?
Get on this camera, Ryder.
You're not part of
the tasting team right now.
How's that ice cream?
I wouldn't know,
because I'm not eating it.
Ryder said he wouldn't know,
because he's not eating it.
The pie filling is
to the next level.
Because the apple still has
so much great texture in it.
There's still
a little bit of crunch,
and it's not
overly sweet.
It's just that fantastic balance
of the cinnamon
and the vanilla
and the sugar.
Ryder, you're going
to come over?
The caramel, the filling,
the fry, but in particular,
the ice cream.
Dynamite job.
-Nice job, Chef.
-Thank you so much.
That's it, everybody.
That's it. Nice job.
High five.
The whole reason we did this
is we wanted to share
with everybody
just how the world's changing,
and you can find some of
your favorite restaurants
all over the country that
are actually doing delivery.
And you can order it and have
it brought to you online.
Look at the experience
we just had.
Four of
our favorite restaurants
from "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
And I don't
typically do this.
There's no prizes,
and there's no cash award.
This is
simply bragging rights.
But ladies and gentlemen,
today's best dish will go to...
Who's it going to go?
Ryder thinks he has it.
I'm going to
tell you something.
She came in
at the last minute
and stole it away
from the Truffle Master.
-Yeah!
-Give it up for Se7enbites.
Chef Trin, congratulations.
Delicious.
-Congratulations
-Nice job, girl.
Thank you so much.
We're going to be eating
leftovers
for like the next week,
but it was really
a dynamite experience.
We'll see you next time
on "Triple-D" Takeout.
Adios.
Peace out.
Well, most people put all their
gloves on at the same time.
I didn't think straight.
Hold on.
We'll be right back.
What is this?
My thumb is stuck.
My pinkie is all bent.