Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
What?
...we're not
messing around...
Everybody, stand back,
she's mixing.
...because Mom and Dad
are in charge of the kitchen.
[ Laughs ]
I've got her laughing now,
we're gonna be here
all week.
They're cooking up
Caribbean soul in Denver...
That's lights out
right there.
...legit Indian right out
of a Utah gas station...
Out of bounds.
...and Chinese dumplings
in Vermont...
It doesn't get any better,
right?
...fired up
by a local legend.
-Dumpling mayor.
-She is the dumpling mayor.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
♪♪
I'm in the Five Points area
of Denver, Colorado.
Now, back in the '40s
and '50s,
this area right here
was the jazz epicenter.
And now things have changed,
and it's the culinary epicenter,
where this family
has been serving up
their Caribbean soul food
for 20 years.
You're gonna love it.
This is the Welton St. Cafe.
I got a oxtail dinner.
It's absolutely unforgettable.
A lot of places sell food...
[ Laughs ]
...but this place sells soul
on top of that.
Catfish dinner.
This actually takes the place
of my mom's cooking.
FIERI: And the mom who's cooking
here is Mona Dickerson.
I might be hipping
and hopping,
but I can move
when the time comes to move.
FIERI: She's been feeding
this part of Denver
since she
and her ex-husband, Flynn,
opened their first joint
in the '80s,
and now she's brought
their kids
into her home cooking mix.
Who taught you how to cook?
My grandma would sit
in a chair here
and she would have me
put everything in a pot for her.
What island
did you come from?
The Virgin Islands,
Saint Thomas.
So it's a Caribbean restaurant
that has a soul food attitude.
We got some jerk chicken
back here.
The food is just amazing.
Favorite thing on the menu?
What's not my favorite thing
on the menu?
That's the answer
I like.
We have a big beef pâté
for you.
Pâté is my number-one
go-to.
It's a full meal
in one nice little package.
What's a pâté?
A pita, a pocket.
So something in dough
that we put meat inside of?
Right. We're gonna make
the ground beef for the pâtés.
I'mma pour a little bit
of pickle juice in here.
Pickle juice is how we're
kicking this thing off?
So the meat wouldn't stick
to the bottom out of pot.
I don't know that I've ever seen
the pickle juice game,
but I'm down with it.
You have some garlic,
tomato.
The method
is garlic, tomato?
You can put anything in.
Just dump the whole
kitchen sink in.
You want help?
I can get the sink.
[ Laughs ]
That's good.
I got two laughs
out of her so far.
Green bell pepper,
some green onions.
Is this jalapeño?
It's jalapeño and habanero.
I don't find the Caribbean food
to be that spicy.
I don't eat spicy.
That was a quarter cup
of jalapeño,
"I don't eat spicy."
[ Chuckles ]
Parsley.
How about some onions?
Salt and pepper.
And did you put
the thyme in?
Yeah, I'm putting a lot
of thyme in right now.
I got -- [ Chuckles ]
[ Laughs ]
Three laughs.
So we're gonna
let this cook,
add the tomato paste,
and then we'll let it cool
and we're gonna make
the dough.
Uh-huh.
I'm in black today.
You running
from the flour, huh?
I'm in. I'm right here.
All-purpose flour, sugar.
Baking powder.
A little bit of salt.
Shortening.
Then we'll hit the water.
We'll mix it for about
seven minutes.
We let it rest, and then
we're ready to make our pâtés.
The most popular one
is the beef and cheese.
Are we making the beef
and cheese?
We can make
a beef and cheese.
Cut off a piece.
Run it through the sheeter.
Now I'm putting
some cheese in here.
We add the filling.
That's big.
We don't do small.
This is my crimper.
I see it.
Now I put it in a pot.
Most people from the islands,
they just order plain beef.
If you come in and you say,
"I need eight beef pâtés,"
I know you came
from the islands.
Yeah, but I won't be able
to say it with a cool accent.
I don't do it that good.
Okay.
What do you do good?
Eat?
[ Both laugh ]
Now,
this is finger food.
That is full.
It's delicious.
It's a full meal.
That's the equivalent
of eating a burger.
The dough is dynamite,
nice and light and tender,
and the filling
is incredibly flavorful.
There's a little bit
of heat,
and I like it
with the cheese.
[ Laughs ]
Ta-da.
The ratio from bread
to filling is fantastic.
It's always juicy
on the inside.
If you want something that's
gonna make you feel good,
it's a great dish to go with.
DICKERSON: What's up with
that fried chicken?
Fried chicken ready.
MAN: Everybody likes good food,
but when you're also around good
people, then it makes it easy.
Yay!
They give me hugs
when I come in,
they give me great food.
What do you do?
I do mentorship for a group
called Denver Gents.
We help the young men
with what we call soft skills,
their dress,
how they're supposed
to talk to young ladies.
It's so necessary
in today's world, I mean...
Super necessary.
And when you tell somebody
about the restaurant,
how do you describe it?
It's legit.
How long you got on them chops?
I'm ready.
There is nothing like when you
get a pork chop
that is fried to perfection
and then someone puts
some gravy on top.
It's just mind-blowing.
FIERI: Fried, smothered,
and greened,
when we come back.
I'm gonna have to change
some schedule.
I'm gonna be here
for a bit.
[ Laughs ]
I bet you do a lot
of working out.
I push the car all around
the country.
I don't even get in it anymore.
I just have to push it.
Okay.
That's the only way
I can work it off.
[ Chuckles ]
So welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out here
in Five Points area of Denver
at the Welton St. Cafe
where
she's holding court.
MAN: Miss Mona is somebody
that you can come to.
It's actually a refuge.
[ Laughs ]
Mona opens her door.
Everybody's welcome.
Yams and mac and cheese.
It's soul food
from the Caribbean.
WOMAN: I love a good oxtail.
Honey hot wings.
Of course, this pork chop,
which is amazing.
Now we're gonna get into
some fried pork chop.
DICKERSON: We're gonna just make
my little seasoning here.
Salt, garlic powder.
You've had to see
this neighborhood change
quite a bit in the 20 years
you've been here?
Oh, yes. Lots, lots, lots.
Black pepper, paprika.
Back in the day, this
was the jazz epicenter, right?
Just about
every other building
had a bar or club
or something.
You don't see that
anymore.
You're kind of like
the unofficial mayor
of this whole area, I bet.
Everybody knows you.
Now I'm gonna
season them up.
So bone-in pork chops.
The flavor is in the bone.
We'll drop in flour, fry them
four minutes on each side.
Nice little shallow fry again.
I like the way you roll.
Now we're ready to make
the gravy.
So we've got
a little bit left
in the bottom of the pan,
lots of flavor.
A little flour.
Onions, garlic,
little bit of salt in here.
Pepper, brown gravy flour,
Kitchen Bouquet.
Nice little color
out of that.
Add the water.
Let it simmer for 15 minutes
and add the pork chops back in.
I like it, and we're gonna do
some greens with this?
Yeah, we can.
Oh, I love greens.
Put the collard greens in.
I mean, that's an elephant ear
right there.
Oh, yeah, it is.
[ Laughs ]
I got her laughing now.
We're gonna be here all week.
Add some garlic
and some onions.
Put a little bit of oil in it to
keep the greens kind of loose.
Got to keep
your greens loose.
Salt, garlic salt, habanero
peppers, some black pepper.
Little chicken base.
I put my big old turkey in.
That's a monster.
How long will you let this cook?
About two hours.
You ready?
Is this enough greens
for you?
Oh, look at that.
I need to rent
one of those booths
to lay down in
and take a nap.
Is that right?
♪♪
Pork chops don't get
as much play as they deserve.
It's impossible
for this pork chop to be dry.
Sits on there
in this bath of gravy.
And the greens,
they've still got a little bite.
They're not mushy. They have
a little bit of that smoke.
That turkey leg,
that's lights out right there.
Well done, my friend.
Pork chop's ready.
The gravy is
absolutely delicious.
With most people's greens, I'm,
like, reaching for hot sauce,
I'm reaching
for salt and pepper.
I come here, I don't reach
for anything but my fork.
That's the truth.
I have enough to feed me
and myself
and I for the next two,
three days.
You're very fortunate to have
a place like this.
They all treat you like family
as well.
They know your name.
Me, myself, and I?
[ Laughs ]
Beautiful.
Whenever I go somewhere else
and eat,
where they're serving soul food,
this is what I compare it to.
You're a rock star.
You've got to come down here
when she's hanging out,
running the show.
Very delicious.
Really enjoyed it.
You're very welcome.
FIERI: Up next,
in Burlington, Vermont...
I'm having this undying
need to shovel this.
...Chinese flavor....
No wonder
everybody loves you.
...starring
a true dumpling diva.
[ Singing
in native language ]
♪♪
So I'm here in Burlington,
Vermont,
not too far from
the University of Vermont,
and I'm looking for
a local culinary celebrity.
People say in these parts
there's a lady
that has a pushcart,
makes amazing Chinese dumplings,
but I've asked around,
and unfortunately,
I'm getting some sad news,
everybody in Flavortown.
Well, she's closed up shop.
[ Exhales sharply ]
But don't worry, she's opened up
a brick-and-mortar,
and this is
Hong's Chinese Dumplings.
Giant steam bell.
Hong's is an institution.
It's literally love
at first bite.
I saw Mrs. Hong
on Church Street.
When she had the pushcart?
Yep. Well, she doesn't
have it anymore.
Yes, not so much.
And then I found
the dumpling temple.
The dumpling temple.
What do you think
makes it so good?
She's like my grandma,
basically.
Your dumpling grandma?
Yes, she's Mama Hong.
FIERI: Or officially Hong Yu,
who came to the U.S.
with her daughter
Lisa in the late '90s,
opened a dumpling cart,
and reached legendary status.
She's got to be, like, the
unofficial mayor of the town.
Dumpling mayor.
She is the dumpling mayor.
I love dumplings.
You don't even understand.
My dumpling issues are...
I mean, I have
to go to counseling.
We're gonna make
pork dumplings
and chicken and cheese?
Yeah.
MAN: The pan-fried taste
with the crunch
and then the chewiness --
They're amazing.
What are we gonna make first?
Flour dough.
Flour dough
for the dumplings.
First flour, water.
[ Singing
in native language ]
You have
a beautiful voice.
♪♪
[ Applause ]
I was gonna join in.
I usually do it as C minor.
Do we have a song
for the ground pork?
I know you can make anything.
Salt, chicken base?
Yeah.
The secret spice.
I smell a lot of Chinese
five spice.
Sugar, ginger, garlic.
Granulated garlic.
Gotcha.
Oil.
Dark soy sauce. Sesame oil.
Cooking wine.
Regular soy.
That's your regular soy sauce.
Okay.
I can mix.
Everybody, stand back,
she's mixing.
Green bell pepper,
white onion.
Yep.
Next type of dumpling is?
Chicken and cheese.
We're in Vermont,
so I'm going with this cheese
in a traditional Chinese
dumpling,
but I'm on the fence
just like you.
So, cooked breast meat,
chicken.
Montreal seasoning.
Tumeric?
Turmeric, yeah.
Paprika?
Yeah, paprika.
Salt, chicken base?
Yeah.
There's sesame oil,
regular soy sauce, and...
Vinegar.
Red and green bell pepper.
The white onion.
Onion, yeah.
That's cheddar cheese.
I can't believe
I am participating
in the cheddar cheese
going in the Chinese dumpling.
I'm not even gonna look.
Are you mixing?
Yes.
I feel a song.
[ Singing
in native language ]
I think she's making
this one up.
♪ I love dumpling ♪
I love you, dumpling.
Okay,
let's make a dumpling.
♪♪
Chicken and cheese.
Wow, you really load it up.
Can we make
the pork one now?
Yeah.
Not shy on the portion.
Now we start to cook them?
Yeah.
Now what?
Sweet and sour.
Sweet and sour
cranberry sauce?
Right.
Orange juice, sugar.
Cranberry, pineapple,
cranberry jelly.
And ketchup.
So we cook that down then?
Yeah, 15 to 20 minutes.
Okay.
Those are big dumplings.
Chopped onions.
[ Whistles ] It's hot.
♪♪
Delicious.
They're probably
the biggest dumplings
I've ever seen.
The chicken and cheese
tastes like a quesadilla.
When you cook the pork raw
inside of the dumpling,
all that flavor
stays inside of there.
I'm having this undying need
to shovel this.
That's good sweet and sour.
I want to buy it by the gallon.
That one. Yes.
[ Laughs ]
What?
WOMAN:
Three pork dumplings
and three chicken and cheese
dumplings.
I like
the chicken and cheese.
Those spices are really,
really good.
The pork with the cranberry
sauce to me is just meant to be.
FIERI: But when Hong was
running her dumpling cart,
the locals couldn't get
their fix year-round.
FIERI: Because the winters
are harsh here,
you didn't have
any dumplings?
No.
I ran a crowdfunding campaign
for my mom to start a restaurant
so they can have dumplings
all the time.
And what else do you make?
We have noodles, rice.
And scallion pancakes?
Scallion pancakes.
The scallion pancakes
are really delicious.
It has this super scallion
flavor and the soy flavor.
It's really amazing.
We make the scallion pancake?
Yes.
The dough is done.
I've never seen this technique
of rolling the dough
around the pin.
Chinese spice into some
scallions and the chicken base.
A little salt?
Salt, yeah.
And some oil?
Yes.
The flavor, I can tell,
is gonna be pow.
Roll.
Massage.
Oh, massage. Oh.
Yeah.
More?
Now we have all the layers
going this way.
Massage again?
Yeah.
What,
are we making a croissant?
Oh, yeah.
You want a song?
[ Singing
in native language ]
I said, "croissant."
Okay, I'm sorry.
Don't come in and ask
for croissants,
you're gonna get a song.
And then we roll it again?
Yeah.
That is a lot of work.
A little salt.
Roll it out by hand.
Then we go to the pan with the
hot oil and fry both sides.
Beautiful.
♪♪
It's flaky,
yet crispy.
What makes this work
is the layering.
Delicious scallions
all the way through.
I came here
for the dumplings.
I didn't know I was gonna get
scallion pancake
with all these delicious sauces.
No wonder everybody loves you.
Scallion pancake
almost done.
They're light, but
they're super flavorful.
It feels like you're eating
something authentic.
Pork dumplings
and cold sesame noodles.
You, like, have a down day
or something,
go visit Hong
and it makes you feel better.
Simple, delicious.
Makes you happy.
It doesn't get
any better, right?
Thank you.
I see why all the people
raised the money for you
because the dumplings are
delicious and you're fantastic.
Do you have
a goodbye song?
♪ Bye ♪
We're leaving.
Can you drive stick shift?
FIERI: Coming up in Logan,
Utah...
Guess what's gonna
happen next?
You're never gonna
believe it.
...a filling station-restaurant
combo...
Oh, my gosh.
I'm telling you.
...pumping out
family specialties
from around the globe.
This is like a passport-free
experience to true Indian food.
♪♪
Boy, did I just roll in
on fumes on that one.
I'm here in Logan, Utah,
about an hour and a half
outside of Salt Lake City.
Now, back in the day,
if you would've said,
"Hey, what are your favorite
'Triple D' joints?"
I would have said,
"Funky Italian joint,
or Chinese
or maybe an Irish pub,"
but these days
I'm looking for Indian food.
Oh, you're seeing it sprout up
all over the country.
Big flavors, great stories,
and I got one for you
right here at a gas station.
This is Tandoori Oven.
Saag paneer on A1,
please.
It's like a smorgasbord
of flavors.
The lamb karahi.
When this restaurant came,
it was a huge welcome
for people to understand
how great Indian food really is.
FIERI: And it's Chef Sham Arora
and his family
who are schooling the locals
about the regional flavors
of their homeland.
FIERI: Northern is more meat
and more sauce?
It's, like, more rich food,
like, more everything.
And when did you come
to the United States?
1997.
And then your whole family's
here now?
Yes.
Everybody work
in the restaurant?
Yeah.
Okay.
How's everything
tasting over here, guys?
I love the lentil bread.
I love the plum sauce.
I love the tikka masala.
Would it be easier to ask you
what you don't like?
Probably. [ Chuckles ]
WOMAN:
The chicken tikka masala.
Today we had
the chicken tikka masala,
which is like
an Indian stew.
MAN: It's creamy.
It has incredible flavor.
You just get
the whole experience.
What are we gonna make?
Chicken tikka masala.
You got to do
the sauces first.
Yeah, we're just going
to make an onion gravy.
Oil, cumin, coriander.
I'm done cutting
all these onions.
Thank you very much
for that.
You're welcome,
very little.
Be careful with those.
I worked on those all day.
Tomato.
In the water.
Next, we have to make
a separate sauce.
Oil, ginger, garlic.
Just garam masala.
Turmeric, paprika.
We'll add it to the onions
and the tomatoes.
We'll hit it with
the immersion blender,
and then the onion gravy
is done.
Then the gravy is done.
Now we're gonna make the
chicken for the tikka masala?
Yes, sir.
Whole milk yogurt,
salt, paprika, turmeric,
garam masala,
and lemon juice.
Ginger, garlic.
Then, little touch of color.
We add some chicken.
48 hours to marinate.
48.
What temperature is the tandoor
oven running at right now?
Almost 400.
Is there wood in there?
"Mystery" charcoal.
You're not gonna tell me?
It's a mystery charcoal.
No, mesquite.
Mesquite charcoal.
I wonder if it's --
oh, mesquite.
Mesquite charcoal.
Thought it was
mystery charcoal.
[ Laughs ]
Chicken's working,
time for the sauce.
Put some little ginger, garlic,
little bell pepper, some cream.
Onion gravy, tomato gravy.
This is the chicken tikka.
And how long does this cook?
And what's in the rice,
Chef?
Cloves, bay leaf,
and cumin seed.
Delicious.
Then, fenugreek leaf,
cilantro.
Tikka masala --
and then good to go, sir.
Now, what is the correct way
to eat this?
Over the rice.
But mostly in Northern India,
we have to scoop the bread.
Well, you just told me
put it over the rice.
♪♪
I'm having anxiety right now
about how to shovel it
in fast enough,
but do it and not look like
I'm the first time a dog
has seen a bowl of food.
♪♪
[ Mouth full ]
This is so good.
This is
very approachable.
That's probably
one of the staple dishes
that people should try
when they're trying
Indian food
for the first time.
Oh, my gosh.
I'm telling you.
Mmm!
Thank you.
The chicken tikka masala
for you.
The chicken is so tender.
My teeth just sink into it.
Perfect blend of spice
and creaminess.
Saag paneer, please.
How did you find
this place?
Oh, my husband said, "We're
gonna go to dinner,"
and we pulled into
a gas station
and I was like,
"You're kidding, right?"
Classy.
FIERI: It's no joke.
Sham and his family
set up shop
right inside
the other business they own.
WOMAN: It started out just as
the gas station
with the family running it,
and then they added on their
first version of Tandoori Oven.
It was a tiny little hole
in the wall.
They've expanded, and now
we've got this beautiful place.
Chicken coconut on C3,
please.
I'll start off the meal
with an appetizer
so that you can
wet your whistle.
My favorite are the samosas.
Samosas are kind of like
an egg-roll-type texture
on the outside,
and then has the meat
and the veggies on the inside.
FIERI: Chef, what are we
gonna make?
Let's see.
First we are to making
keema filling.
A little oil.
Guess what's gonna
happen next?
You're never gonna
believe it.
Cumin seed.
Didn't see that coming.
Let me guess --
ginger, garlic?
Yeah.
You should have named one of
your grandkids Ginger, Garlic.
This is my grandkids
Ginger,
he got stuck with Garlic.
Ground lamb?
Yes, sir.
Turmeric, paprika,
garam masala, chaat masala.
Chard or chaat?
Chaat. C-H-A-A-T.
Two A's together?
Two double.
Two double A's.
Or you can make one A.
I don't want to make one A,
then it's chat.
Coriander, salt.
Oh, and pass the peas,
please.
This is ready to go.
Now we're gonna
make the dough.
Flour, salt. Carom seeds.
Carom seeds?
Yeah. Oil.
And some water?
Yes, sir.
How long
is this going to mix?
Five minutes.
And then we let it rest?
Like one hour.
Got it.
Cut it in half.
Okay.
Little water
and just do like that.
Oh, I'm making meat
in a cone.
And then fill it up
like that.
And we're gonna
fry these.
Beautiful.
♪♪
Mmm.
You've got to have
the mint chutney.
Super refreshing,
really bright.
Everything's fresh.
We don't use any artificial
anything in there.
Not even hair color.
[ Chuckles ]
What?
This is a great samosa.
A lot of flavor,
a lot of filling, good balance.
The lamb filling
is outrageous.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
Here are some samosas.
You're having the crispy,
the soft, the heat, the sweet.
Absolutely perfect.
These are friends of mine.
This is Nick, Jack, and Julie.
Jack is actually a chef from one
of my favorite companies,
a group called Camp Chef.
In the world of Indian food,
how do you think these folks do?
Very top.
I always leave here with a smile
on my face,
and if it was possible
for our stomachs to have mouths,
there would be a smile
down there as well.
FIERI: This is like
a passport-free experience
to true Indian food.
Out of bounds.
It's out.
[ Laughs ]
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry,
there's plenty more
"Triple D" joints
all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
You ready?
Yes.
Okay.
That's good.
Oh, now we're drumming.
Right.
We sang last time.
Now it's a drumming time.
We need help.
[ Laughter ]
People are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because Triple D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip, a place
pitching major league burgers.
Go big or go home.
Or come here and go home big.
And spreading the love
all over Massachusetts.
Give me a hug.
All right.
That's what I'm talking about.
Plus an Italian joint in Boston,
not skipping on the portions.
Because there's nothing left
in the ocean now?
Or the palate.
Awesome. Primo.
And it's a "Triple D" first.
The sirens are going off,
the flood of Flavortown.
Where a ramen spot in El Paso
becomes an overnight sensation.
The last meal I had last night,
the first meal I had today.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D" Nation.
♪♪
On "Triple D" Nation, it's not
about a bunch of firsts.
Most of the places we're
visiting I've been to before.
Going back there to see
how things are going,
but today, well,
I've got a first for you.
I'm here in El Paso, Texas,
and just last night
I was having some
fantastic ramen with my buddies,
and I got done eating.
I said, you know what?
We've got to feature this on
"Triple D" Nation.
This is Kaedama.
♪♪
Bowl in, order up.
These two gentlemen were
the first ones
to actually
introduce ramen to our city.
They hit a home run.
It's just
absolutely delicious.
You can taste the care
that they take
putting
this bowl together.
FIERI: That's dude-up
ramen ringleaders
Andres Romero
and Gabe Valencia,
good buddies of mine for --
let's see, over 12 hours.
I come to El Paso,
I get done shooting "Triple D."
Everybody's hungry.
We wanted a place to eat.
Want some ramen.
We tracked down
this funky little spot.
Mind you, this is
all last night.
You know, I was talking
to you last night.
Right.
So let's go
from the beginning.
Are people of El Paso,
are they tuned in
to what great ramen is?
Valencia: Most in El Paso had no
idea what it was,
so it had to be good.
We're the ones
that introduced them to it.
-You got to set the bar high.
-Yeah.
I had the dipping ramen.
Yeah, that's called
a tsukemen.
Instead of the noodles
sitting inside of a broth.
The broth
is on the side.
And it is a dish
I hadn't had before.
It's concentrated broth.
It's thicker, a little saltier.
You dip your noodles in there
and then eat them.
FIERI: But the crown jewel
of this place is the tonkotsu.
The tonkotsu,
that's the house bowl.
VALENCIA:
That's our flagship.
Tonkotsu, no egg.
What are we using
to build the stock,
the base
of this great ramen?
VALENCIA:
Pork feet and water.
-Pig's feet and water.
And it's going to boil
for 12 hours.
That's a lot of pig's feet.
We're heads and feet
above the rest.
Now we're going to make the...
which is the seasoning.
The...
sets kind of the tone
for what the flavor of the bowl
is gonna be.
Yeah. This is all the
personality of each bowl.
Minced garlic.
-Okay.
Dashi, It's as smoked bonito
flake powder, minced ginger.
Salt.
We're a good team.
I'm going to start work here
on my off weeks.
-Sugar.
-That's it.
That's the batter
right there.
-So the noodles.
-Sun noodles.
Sun noodles out of Hawaii.
That's the Cadillac of noodles.
All right,
so we dropped the noodles.
Cook them
for about two minutes.
To me, this is one of
the most important factors.
You have to have the ability
to drain that water off,
and you have a backup
going at the same time.
Once one of the baskets
gets a little too starchy,
we switch over
to the other one.
Flush the water, cycle it.
We're good to go.
Smart man. Super smart.
And then we build a bowl
from the noodle.
-Right.
-So the...goes in first.
These noodles in here later.
Ladle this broth.
Look at the color of that broth
just from cooking down
those pork feet.
Love it.
Mix that into the broth.
Scallions.
The sirens are going off
with flood in Flavortown.
-Narutomakis.
-Pork belly.
Blackened garlic oil.
Right there, it's ready to go.
Where do you go?
I go broth. I just want to see
what the broth is like.
♪♪
It's creamy. It's rich.
It coats your mouth, your salt's
right, your seasoning's right.
That's a pretty
broad spectrum of flavors.
♪♪
I ate that ramen bowl.
I am "good night."
Last meal I had last night,
the first meal I had today.
SERVER:
Here's your tonkotsu.
The flavor pops.
Saltiness, not too spicy.
The pork belly is delicious.
It breaks apart on your tongue
as soon as you eat it.
So fresh.
The meat was tender,
complemented the noodles
very well.
WOMAN:
What I love about this place
is that you finish the bowl,
you get another one.
You can order Kaedama.
Once your noodles are done,
get a whole other batch
of noodles in there.
It's like two bowls in one.
How many different types
of ramen are we doing, Gabe?
We offer six bowls.
There's a couple of bowls
that have an El Paso flair
to them.
The chipotle one.
We decided to incorporate
a little bit of spice
into our bowl.
We're going to start off
with making the seasoning mix --
onion powder, garlic powder,
ginger powder,
smoked paprika,
and some salt.
Sprinkle it
on our chicken breasts
and stick it in the oven.
We're going to make our...
which is our seasoning
for the bowl.
Salts, sugar, smoked paprika,
fire-roasted tomatoes,
whole garlic cloves,
miso paste, a little bit
of water, some onions.
And last is
the star of the show,
the chipotle pepper
and adobo sauce.
We're just going to go ahead
and blend it up,
and right there
it's ready to go.
So this is the chicken
we just roasted,
ready to brown on our flattop.
So now we're ready to assemble
our chipotle bowl.
We're going to put our...
noodles,
gonna pour a little bit
of veggie broth in there,
scallions, sweet corn,
fire roasted diced tomatoes,
chicken,
one of our marinated eggs,
sesame seeds, chile threads.
Chipotle, order up.
The chipotle bowl
is my favorite.
Spices are balanced out.
It's like a tomato-y chipotle
kind of broth. It's delicious.
It's not too spicy,
it's not overwhelming.
The chicken is real tender.
It's good flavor.
♪♪
Never has it happened like this.
I was just here for dinner.
I mean, I went from here
to my hotel back here.
I was so inspired,
because if we ever talk
about what it takes to make it
in the restaurant business,
you two are
a shining example of that.
That's blood,
sweat and tears, guys,
and here's
your graduation present.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
-You never know baby, right?
-Appreciate it.
Smart guys.
FIERI: Now, coming up...
It's not Flavortown.
It's "Flava-town."
FIERI:
A Boston burger joint hitting
home runs all over this state.
Wicked good, wicked killer,
wicked awesome.
FIERI:
When I hit up a burger joint,
I'm looking
for something special,
something out of the box,
and this place in Boston
did not disappoint.
Table three,
Killer Bee.
These days, they're rocking
four locations, a food truck,
and a burger named
for one of Beantown's
biggest baseball legends.
This is
the Boston Burger Company.
♪♪
Table five, Sophie.
WOMAN:
I saw this place on "Triple D,"
so I had to come and check it
out, and it's fantastic.
If you want the best burger
in Boston,
you definitely got to come
to Boston Burger.
All the burgers here at
Boston Burger are really unique.
It's one of the things that can
keep you coming back for years.
FIERI: And we're back, too,
thanks to owner Paul Malvone,
who I met back in 2012.
But that wasn't his first time
in the spotlight.
My girl Rachael Ray, she gave
you props about your burgers.
Yes.
Before "Triple D" came in, we
were on the "Rachael Ray Show."
It was a competition
we happened to win.
I got a hug on the show.
A hug? Really?
Don't think you're
getting that from me.
[ Laughs ]
You will.
So what are we making?
What kind of burger
are you making me?
We're making the Mac Attack.
That's just what I need.
We're gonna make some
mac and cheese, gonna
make the cheese sauce.
Take our chopped onions,
the butter.
We're gonna
let that sweat up.
Throw the flour
right in.
So we've got the roux built,
cooked out the flour.
Got the onions in there.
Now we're gonna
go with some milk?
Gonna go with some milk.
Cheeses.
American,
some cheddar.
Cheddar,
wicked cheddar.
Wicked good, wicked killer,
wicked awesome.
You have the accent.
It's not Flavortown.
It's "Flava-town."
[ Laughs ]
Now we're doing some
shredded cheddar-Jack cheese.
So stir it up.
Get it done.
Boil some water, make some
pasta, and there we go?
Absolutely.
Alright.
Cheese sauce is made.
Hot sauce.
♪♪
New ingredient
I'm adding
to my mac and cheese
flavor profiles -- hot sauce.
Where's that been
all my life?
Andale, mi amigo.
Gonna throw some Parmesan,
little Pecorino Romano,
and we're gonna throw in
some salt and pepper.
I'm just gonna mix
this right up.
Now you dump it in the pan,
let it set up overnight?
Absolutely. If it's too hot,
it's gonna fall apart.
Too hot, it'll fall apart.
Okay.
We'll throw a burger right down.
Okay, nice 80/20.
Throw on some bacon.
Throw that right on the grill.
Put some
cheddar-Jack cheese on.
♪♪
I'm gonna get, like, one of
those road construction signs
on my heart.
Look at this.
Mac Attack.
♪♪
Mmm!
Really good meat
in the burger.
♪♪
Good chew, good texture,
good fat.
I understand why Rachael
gave you a hug.
[ Laughs ]
I'm still
not getting one?
We'll talk about it.
Alright.
Mac Attack,
when we first started,
we'd sell, you know,
maybe 10, 15 a day or so,
but now we sell thousands
of Mac Attack burgers a month.
If you're gonna go
for a big burger,
putting mac and cheese
on it's pretty gangster.
Go big or go home.
Or come here
and go home big.
It's their new slogan.
FIERI: And he took that slogan
and ran with it.
Before "Triple D" came in,
we had a 28-seat restaurant.
After the show aired, we
doubled our seating capacity,
four restaurants now,
a food truck.
FIERI: Plus, he added
a couple new all-stars.
MALVONE:
A Big Papi Burger.
We collaborated
with David Ortiz,
so the proceeds goes
towards his charity.
So we're gonna be making
our homemade guacamole.
First, we're gonna
mash up our avocados.
We're gonna add tomatoes,
chopped red onion,
pickled jalapeño.
Got to have
a little heat in there.
Fresh-cut cilantro,
black pepper,
salt, and some lime juice.
And we're gonna
mix that all together.
We're good with the guacamole.
We're all set and ready to go.
That is certified Angus beef.
We'll add the bacon
and the hot dog to the grill.
It's all gonna go
on top of the burger.
Once it's all cooked,
at the very end,
we're gonna fry our egg.
Complete our burger --
lettuce, two slices of tomato,
little sprinkle of black pepper.
We're gonna plate the burger
on top of that,
guacamole, house-made
pickled red onions, fried egg,
that Papi sauce,
which is ketchup,
a lot of sugar, paprika,
sriracha, white wine vinegar.
Then just a little bit of water.
Turn up the heat.
Mix that all together.
Mix that in
with some mayonnaise,
and it's a sweet, tangy,
creamy deliciousness.
The Big Papi.
Big Papi's a big name here.
That's why they have
a big burger named after him.
A filling, flavorful,
just an amazing burger.
MAN: It's huge, and the sauce
is really, really tasty
and totally unique.
I've eaten here many,
many, many a times,
and every single burger
is very, very good.
The Big Papi's excellent.
The big mac burger is very good.
The Sophie burger's
phenomenal, as well.
The Sophie burger is one of
our most popular burgers now.
Sophie is actually
a real person.
She's a tour guide in Italy.
So we're gonna make
our lemon vinaigrette.
We're gonna add
a little olive oil, lemon juice,
honey, some Dijon mustard,
salt, pepper, white vinegar.
And we're just gonna
whisk that up.
We're gonna take our burger,
give it a flip.
Top that with some prosciutto
and goat cheese.
It's not gonna melt.
It's gonna get a little soft.
We're gonna add our salad,
the house-made
lemon vinaigrette.
Burger right on top.
Crushed candied walnuts,
balsamic glaze, fig jam.
And there it is --
a little bit salty, very sweet,
and just a little nuts,
like Sophie is.
WOMAN: Sophie burger
has that perfect taste
of sweet and tangy
at the same time
because of the goat cheese.
WOMAN #2:
You have the prosciutto
and you have to fig jam
with the vinaigrette.
It balances everything out
very nicely.
You totally recommend it
to anybody that's a burger fan.
Highly recommend.
It's wicked awesome.
Give me a hug.
Alright.
That's what I'm talking about.
There you go. See?
[ Laughs ]
Sophie's got a burger.
Big Papi has a burger.
And I'm assuming
at some point in time,
"Triple D" burger
is in the works.
Am I right, Paul?
Alright, coming up,
we're staying in Boston...
You smell the garlic.
You smell --
I'm saying it like him.
...where these Italian dudes
are cooking up classics
that you just can't
get enough of.
My flavor jets
have just turned on.
Boston is one of those cities
known for their
melting pot of flavors.
You've got Korean, Vietnamese,
Colombian, Pakistani.
I mean, you name it.
Back in 2012,
I just couldn't help myself.
I had to go check out
everybody's go-to favorite,
that tried and true Italian.
Sausage cacc and ziti.
And they're still kicking out
some killer dishes.
This is
Italian Express Pizzeria.
Don't be skimpy.
Let's go.
Tastes just like my grandmother
used to make.
I think Guy picked a great spot
for his show.
I agree with that.
I've heard that I look like Guy.
I've know Jimmy and Jon
for almost 50 years.
They've got a golden heart
and a golden touch
in the kitchen, that's for sure.
FIERI: That would be
long-time buddies
Jimmy Iannuzzi
and Jonathan Harker.
What does Jonathan
do here?
Jonathan looks great,
takes care of himself,
and I work
a million hours a week.
Really?
Yeah.
That's nice, Jonathan.
People can't forget
these two faces.
Or the Italian dishes
they're cranking out.
Where'd you learn to cook?
My grandmother.
Dig it.
Yep. Nonni.
When we were on "Triple D,"
we made our homemade fettuccine
with our frutti di mare.
Frutti di mare,
here it is.
Now we're gonna make
my famous pasta sauce, marinara.
Famous?
Famous.
Okay.
Everything here's famous.
Everything's world-famous.
You know, we said
it was back then,
but now it really is.
Fresh chopped onions.
Chopped garlic.
Starting to smell good?
Fantastic.
Take our sauce,
just dump this in here.
While he's doing this, my flavor
jets have just turned on.
There's something
about tomato sauce.
You smell the garlic.
You smell --
I'm saying it like him.
Salt, pepper,
fresh chopped basil.
Stir it up.
And just let it go
low and slow.
About three hours.
Magic's gonna happen.
We're gonna
steam our clams.
So we have our mussels
and our littlenecks.
Some white wine.
Turn the heat on.
Little chicken stock.
Mussels.
Alright, there we go.
And the littleneck clams.
And a little cover.
That's it.
We're gonna start
our sauce.
Butter,
fresh chopped garlic,
some white wine,
some chicken stock.
I want to take
our delicious marinara.
♪♪
Alright,
gonna take some salt,
fresh chopped onion,
some crushed red pepper.
We're gonna cover it.
These are done.
Okay.
Gonna strain the juice.
Look at that.
Alright.
I'm gonna take my shrimp,
calamari.
Let's just let that cook
for a couple seconds.
Now the handmade
semolina fettuccine.
That's right.
Salted water.
All of it?
Yeah.
Then it's gonna be
enough for 18 people.
Ridiculous.
This is one of the most
popular dishes here.
'Cause there's nothing left
in the ocean now?
That's --
♪♪
Mmm! Seafood's
cooked perfectly.
Pasta's got nice bite
to it.
I'm impressed.
Awesome.
FIERI: But they're not
just pulling from the sea.
We're gonna be making
veal saltimbocca
with the homemade fettuccine.
Take our veal
and we're gonna pound it.
You don't want
to pound them too thin
because they'll cook real fast.
And, you know, you got
to have a veal guy.
I had a fish guy.
I still do.
You got to have a fish guy.
Yeah, no, listen.
I say it all the time.
You got to have a great butcher.
You got to have
a great hairstylist.
Right.
A good bail bondsman
and an incredible fishmonger.
You got to
have a fish guy.
But you got to have a veal guy.
We're gonna take this
and just dredge them
in white unbleached flour,
and we're gonna put it
in the pan with some olive oil
and we're gonna cook it
till it's nice and golden brown.
Now we're gonna make
our saltimbocca sauce.
Butter.
I got a butter guy, too.
I'm only kidding.
Marsala wine.
This gives all the flavor.
Fresh mushrooms.
Add our veal.
Parma prosciutto.
Place these on the veal.
Mozzarella cheese.
Melt that all on top.
Slide the veal on top
of my homemade fettuccine.
Fresh parsley.
Veal saltimbocca,
homemade fettuccine.
MAN:
The veal is so tender.
Ham and the cheese
over a bed of fresh fettuccine.
And it's just to die for.
Unbelievable.
It's the freshest veal.
It's phenomenal.
And the portion's always huge.
It's ridiculous.
It's delicious.
Fresh as can be.
It's fun.
You know what?
When you say fun, you exude fun.
"It's fun."
[ Chuckles ]
FIERI: And coming up...
You're gonna
have so much fun.
Eating this fish.
...the fun just doesn't stop,
with more pasta, Parm...
So tell me about
good eggplant Parm.
...and personality.
What are you looking at?
FIERI:
We're in Boston touching base
with a joint I came across
in 2012.
FIERI: There's a lot of Italian
restaurants in Boston.
Lord knows I've eaten
at half of them.
How do you
describe yourself?
No thrills, home-cooked,
family-type neighborhood joint.
And they're whipping up
the dishes to prove it.
This will also involve
some type of me
sleeping in the Camaro
down the street at a park,
just like usual.
Haddock Margarita.
We made a dish with Guy
called the Haddock Margarita.
You know, we said it was fun.
You're gonna have
so much fun.
Eating this fish.
Yeah.
What are you looking at?
Your grandma made
margarita haddock?
Nonni used to make this
when we were kids.
Let's go.
So we got a fillet of haddock.
Beautiful fillet.
Fun time.
[ Party horn blows ]
Dredge the fish
in the flour.
Season?
Nope, just plain
white flour.
Olive oil in the pan.
Okay.
Let that get
a little warm.
Then we're gonna take the fish
and cover it in the egg.
Put this right
in the hot oil.
While this is cooking up here,
we're gonna start our sauce.
Okay.
First we're gonna
take our butter,
pinch of salt,
pinch of black pepper.
This fish is fun. Fun fish.
I'm having a ball.
White wine,
chicken stock.
Okay.
Gonna take some lemon,
a squeeze of lemon in here.
♪♪
Look at that?
That perfect?
Right in this sauce.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Here we go.
I'm just gonna cover this
for a couple minutes.
Take the fish.
Wow, it's just about
ready to fall apart.
Yeah.
Whoa!
You can do it.
Almost.
Go, go, go, go.
There was one little mistake.
I wouldn't call it a mistake.
Ooh.
Is that a problem?
The Russian judge
gives him an 8.
Oh, there you go.
And this is how your grandma
would make it?
That's it.
This how Nonni would do it.
Awesome. Primo.
Simple, pure,
super fresh.
Thank you.
I was pretty proud
to have Guy sit there
and eat the whole thing.
You know,
that's quite a compliment.
FIERI: But I'm not the only
recognizable face at this joint.
♪♪
We had Mayor Menino.
He was part of our episode.
So tell me about
good eggplant Parm.
Well, it's good cheese,
good sauce,
and nice and tender
eggplant.
This is the best.
These guys do it right.
They do it right.
That was quite an honor,
then to have our new mayor,
Marty Walsh, come was another
great honor for us.
Chicken Parm ravioli,
Mr. Mayor.
The chicken Parm's amazing.
Ravioli's great.
♪♪
White meat, free-range chicken.
Pound it out,
dredge it in flour,
egg wash, plain bread crumbs.
Panfry these.
Nonni's marinara sauce,
mozzarella cheese.
Put it in our pizza oven and
let it cook for a few minutes.
Ravioli, put them in a hot,
salted water.
And then we're gonna plate them.
Chicken Parm ravioli.
Chicken Parm's crispy on the
outside, tender on the inside.
Nice mozzarella.
Sauce just accents it.
It's just a great meal.
Melts in your mouth.
Oh, 1,000% I'm taking it home.
[ Chuckles ]
Since Guy was here,
the place has kind of exploded.
It literally happened
overnight.
We want to just keep
a good thing going,
keep making people happy
with our one location.
Yeah, we can't be
two places at once.
We want to be here.
So what we decided was we would
just really expand our patio
to be able to
accommodate more people.
Another benefit,
we've been able to catch up
on a lot of our bills.
Look at that, huh?
I got a Lamborghini.
I got a Ferrari.
We have two red Vespas.
I got a Bentley.
I don't have
any of that stuff.
You guys
are awesome, man.
-I get it.
-Thank you guys.
I'm a fan.
When you've got multiple mayors
busting down your door,
you know you hit the big time.
And so do the fellas at Kaedama,
who introduced ramen
to the residents of El Paso,
and Paul
at Boston Burger Company,
who's naming burgers
after big shots
and taking over the town.
Plus there are plenty
of other places
knocking them out of the park,
and we'll check them out
next time on "Triple D Nation."
[ Laughs ]
Show me what Sammy looks like
when he dances.
Oh, he's like...
That's how Sammy dances.
Really?
Swear to God, just like that.
I wouldn't call that dancing.
I'd call that having a tic.
Yeah, your boy's moving around.
Yeah, there's something
going on.
[ Laughs ]