Hey, everybody. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives."
This trip...
It's really nice.
...lights-out chefs...
Hut, hut. Go!
...baking their roots
right into their menus.
This is an adventure.
What next?
There's Louisiana love
in Utah...
Lots of big flavor.
...Israeli with a twist
in Oregon...
Yes, I'll have
one of those.
...and a funky pizza joint...
Yeah, ha ha!
...giving Denver
a taste of Detroit.
You going to give me
a ta-da or anything?
Ta-da!
[ Laughs ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in the Highlands
neighborhood of Denver,
Colorado, about a mile away
from Citizen Pictures.
Who's Citizen Pictures,
you ask?
Well, it is the team that makes
"Diners, Drive-ins & Dives"
happen, right here.
Now listen, I come into
town and say,
"I'm looking
for something to eat."
They said, "Have you ever
heard of Detroit-style pizza?
It is the bomb."
Real deal?
-ALL: Yeah!
-It better be.
This is Blue Pan.
♪♪
313 in the window
in one minute.
Blue Pan Pizza is my favorite
restaurant in Denver, bar none.
Order in.
It's the best and most authentic
Detroit-style pizza around.
FIERI: And it's two authentic
Michigan natives,
Giles Flanagin
and Jeff "Smoke" Smokevitch,
who are introducing
the Mile High City
to a taste of the Motor City.
Where does the name
Blue Pan come from?
It was an auto parts pan
which the Detroit-style pizza
was created in,
and a gentleman from Sicily
was trying to recreate
a Sicilian pizza.
The pan can withstand
very high heat.
Cheese caramelized
against the pan, and voilà.
Here's your Detroit-style
Brooklyn Bridge.
The Brooklyn Bridge
is my favorite.
WOMAN: The meat, the pepperoni,
the ricotta --
it's the perfect balance
of sauce, cheese, and toppings.
It's just mouth-watering.
All right,
let's get into it.
We're going to make the dough
for the Detroit-style pizza.
High-gluten flour.
I'm going to start this up.
Diastatic malt,
yeast, cold water,
the pre-ferments going in.
Smells great.
Sea salt,
and then I go olive oil.
Let this proof?
This is like
a 17-to-24-hour proof.
All right.
We're going to make
our Detroit-style pizza sauce.
Let's see it.
Crushed tomatoes here,
with skin.
I like how you back up.
Well, it's not --
-You've seen this before?
-Yeah, it's not the first rodeo.
Crushed, without skin.
Okay.
Filets.
And then our sweet condensed
tomatoes, black pepper.
What was that special
little thing you said?
Black.
Oregano, sea salt,
and our olive oil.
Then we immersion blend it.
Okay, brother.
So we're proofed?
Now I want to par-bake it.
Aged white cheddar.
Bake that how long?
Six, seven minutes. 450 degrees.
Got it.
I'm going to rub it with garlic.
Mozzarella?
Mozzarella and Wisconsin
brick too.
Pizza sauce.
Is this your guys' style
of doing this,
or if I go to Detroit,
I'll see them putting
the racing stripes down?
Detroit is racing stripes
down the middle,
traditionally,
on top of the cheese.
Our cup and char pepperoni.
Small, it's got
the casing around it.
Right? It'll bubble up.
It'll make these little oil...
Yeah.
Italian sausage.
So this will go back
in the oven at what temp?
600.
Eight, 10 minutes
and we'll be done?
Right.
Ricotta dollops.
Keep it in the knees.
Keep your back straight.
Sicilian oregano,
Romano cheese.
There we go.
♪♪
The dough is nice and light
and airy,
but there's good chew.
The caramelized cheese
on the outside
is like every bite
of the great grilled cheese
you wanted as a kid.
Tomato sauce is
nice and fresh.
It's dynamite.
Fantastic.
Thanks.
Brooklyn Bridge, finishing up.
MAN: Those little cups of
pepperoni with a little oil
that's kind of swimming
in the bowl, I love that.
MAN: And then when you get
to the crust,
there is just
absolutely nothing like it.
FIERI: And for more highlights,
let's turn to a former pro QB
and college football analyst,
Brian Griese.
[ Whistle blows ]
You think it's this deep,
heavy, you know, Chicago thing.
FIERI: Exactly. Exactly.
It is not. It is light
and fluffy and perfect.
Do you see him moving
right out of the analyst thing
into the food thing now?
[ Laughing ]
He's working his way
into my career zone.
You stay in your own lane.
And you know Smoke because
you guys played ball together.
Smoke and I were on the
same team at Michigan,
the 1997 National
Championship Team.
How interesting that he just
was able to drop that
into the conversation.
[ Laughing ]
Charcuterie.
Who else was on your team?
Charles Woodson,
and you probably heard
of this guy, Tom Brady.
Oh, yeah. He plays still,
doesn't he?
Yeah, he's still
going somewhere.
FIERI: And here, Smoke's
still scoring points
with more than just pizza.
Eggplant fries for the bar.
The eggplant fries
are crunchy and tasty.
Everyone's sick of the same old,
"You want fries with that?"
No, I don't want fries
with that.
I want these kind of fries
because no one else has done it.
Now what are we making?
Eggplant fries.
I'm going to peel
the eggplant first.
Glad I tuned in for this.
[ Chuckles ]
Cut the ends off.
Well, get all angry
about it then.
Dredge them in flour,
2% milk,
and some water,
and then cracker meal.
And then into the fryer?
For five or six minutes.
We going to serve
a sauce with this?
Yeah, we're doing
a house-made marinara.
-Give me the rundown.
-Olive oil, heat it up some.
Onions, shallots.
I mean, wouldn't you say
something like shal-lot?
Say it how I did
the black pepper?
Yeah. Black pepper.
Sweating those out.
Then I got my garlic going.
Sweating to the oldies.
And now food mill.
Plum tomatoes.
Yeah!
How fast can you food mill this
to get it in there
before the onions
and the garlic burn below it?
♪♪
Saporito tomatoes,
Super Dolce, water,
and now we're putting our
sachet with fresh parsley
and bay leaves.
Salt and pepper.
How long is this
going to cook down?
Three to four hours.
All right, let's see it.
Sea salt here.
Grated Romano, marinara,
and garlic aioli on the side.
Are you going to give me
a "ta-da" or anything?
Ta-da!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
I don't think I've ever had
an eggplant fry.
You wouldn't be able to tell me
ever in a million years
it's an eggplant.
Got tons of crunch
on the exterior of this.
It's silky and smooth and like
melted cheese on the inside.
That's probably some of the
best way I've ever had eggplant.
That's really awesome.
Thanks for introducing me
to another fried thing
that I got to have.
[ Laughs ]
WOMAN:
The eggplant fries are amazing.
It's a good mix of veggies
and that fried taste.
The sauce is delicious.
It's got a nice pop to it.
The Chicago Louis Louis,
side of giardiniera.
I introduced earlier
the Citizen Pictures team.
This is where you bring me,
and you're lucky
because if it wasn't dynamite,
they were going to pay.
There's lots of pizza places
in Denver.
Right.
No Detroit-style pizza.
I had never heard of it,
and it's just incredible.
First time
we've ever done it,
and the first time having my
Citizen Pictures team on camera,
not being edited
out of the show.
Meatballs with marinara.
Everything about this place
is literally heaven on earth.
FIERI:
The whole attitude and energy
of the way you guys do things
is something different,
but I'll tell you what, man,
it is super well-received.
-Awesome place.
-Thanks.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next,
in Portland, Oregon...
Dynamite, man.
...a one-of-a-kind joint...
It's a made-for-TV movie.
You could play me.
[ Laughs ]
...taking vegan all the way
to the Middle East.
Stamp the passport
to Flavortown.
You've just crossed the border.
Let me see these.
Ohh-oh-oh!
Now what is that
right over there?
Which one?
All right, let's go ahead
and get this out.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Love coming up
to Portland, Oregon.
Food scene always
going next level.
And talking about going next
level, listen to this story.
Here to check out a joint
where the chef,
he's from an Argentinean family.
He was born in Israel.
Then the family
moved to California.
Now he's up here in Portland.
He's got a hummus company,
he's got a vegan
ice cream company,
and in his spare time, oh, yeah,
he's got a vegan restaurant.
This is Aviv.
♪♪
Falafel pita, medium.
I don't think there's really
anything like it.
Shakshuka.
It's the only
Mediterranean restaurant
that is entirely vegan.
You can bring people here
and they will get as much flavor
and as much texture and as much
uniqueness as any restaurant.
I brought
my mom and dad here,
and they are definitely meat
eaters, and they loved it.
FIERI: That unique menu here
comes from the fact
that when Tal Caspi
cut out the meat,
he kept the flavors
he grew up on.
I thought to myself,
I'm from the Middle East,
I'm going to do
Middle Eastern food.
You're from the Middle East?
I'm from Israel, yeah.
My parents are Argentinean.
How's the menu here?
Explain to me the --
We use a lot of mushrooms.
Mushroom calamari.
The mushroom calamari,
the spices that they use
are really good,
and then they add
that tahini sauce on the side.
It's nice and garlicky
and really flavorful.
Give me the rundown.
All right.
We are going
to make mushroom calamari.
Calamari is something
I've always missed,
so I definitely wanted it
on our menu.
We're going to make
our wet bath first.
-Our what?
-Wet bath. Is that...
-Our wet bath?
-Wet bath. Is that the right --
Oh, versus the dry bath?
Yes. I'll have one of those.
Some aquafaba.
Aqua fava bean?
Bean water, Aleppo pepper.
Okay.
Which is from Aleppo in Syria.
Some kombu.
Seaweed ground up.
Exactly. That gives it
the fishy flavor. Urfa biber.
Oh, the old Urfa biber.
No clue what that is, folks.
It's a wonderful pepper
from Turkey. Salt.
I didn't know you could get
pepper from turkey.
We're going to mix
this all up.
Oh, the country.
The country.
So this is going to coat as well
as add flavor to,
because we're going
to get into a dredge.
Some rice flour, corn meal,
and mix it all up.
-And we're frying this in?
-Canola oil.
And that's all she wrote.
What's next?
Tahini. We got lemon juice,
garlic, water,
tahini paste,
salt, cilantro.
Blend it up.
♪♪
I'll have a cup of that
to go.
-Excellent.
-Next step?
We're going to make
some za'atar,
which is a Middle Eastern
spice blend.
Toasted sesame seeds,
thyme, caraway.
Don't get carried away.
I was going to do it.
Thank you very much.
Glad you did it.
Salt.
-Turmeric?
-Turmeric.
Just shout it out
when you know the answers.
Oregano, ground dill seeds,
and we just mix it up.
-All right.
-Let's see it.
Mushroom calamari,
some tahini, salt,
a good amount of za'atar,
and a lemon wedge
that's been dipped in za'atar.
♪♪
Delicious, thoughtful,
well executed.
Anything you fry,
if you fry it right,
I think you've got
something going for you.
You can fry a shoe
and it's delicious.
Yeah, flip-flop too.
Call it calamari,
call it fried mushrooms,
whatever,
you call it delicious.
And don't call me late
for a second serving.
Excellent.
Thank you, Chef.
I've got a mushroom calamari
for table two.
I think mushroom is a great
option to do as calamari,
because it kind of does have
that same texture
as regular calamari.
Za'atar seasoning
is really good.
Gives it
a little Israeli flair.
Got a hummus ful
for table seven.
Give me the five-minute story
of how this all came together.
I had a food cart, then I
stopped doing the food cart.
We decided to open
a catering company.
We did a pop-up
for the catering company,
and then we opened
Aviv 10 days later.
So I have a packaged
hummus company.
I have a packaged
vegan ice cream company.
We run all that out of here.
Out of here?
-Mm-hmm.
-It's a made-for-TV movie.
You could play me.
Um...
[ Laughs ]
This is an adventure.
What next?
-Shawarma fries.
Easily one of my favorite things
in the whole world.
It's definitely
really delicious.
Let me finish these and then
we'll make
shawarma fries.
See you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back. "Triple D"
hanging out in Portland at Aviv.
They do a really cool
thing here.
They take these
traditional Israeli dishes
and then just kind of put
a vegan spin on them.
He's perfect on seasoning.
It's all super fresh.
So it's legit food, done right,
great ingredients,
local ingredients,
and oh, yeah, on the sidebar,
it happens to be vegan.
Yes. Yes.
Got a shawarma fry
for table three.
Tell me about
shawarma fries.
It's a classic. It's just
soy curls and potatoes.
Just soy curls,
like you see them every day.
Yeah.
[ Laughter ]
You got a ton of different
flavors and texture in there.
I think it's great.
What are we making?
The shawarma fries.
What are we making
the shawarma out of?
Soy curls. This has
no flavor whatsoever.
You can add
any flavor you want.
If you think about something
like chicken piccata, piccata
is the sauce and the flavor,
and that's what we like.
Chicken is the texture
and the vehicle for the sauce.
This is our vehicle.
Hot water, amino acids.
Garlic, curry powder,
garam masala.
Gonna add our soy curls.
The masher works
really well to mix this.
-How long's this going to steep?
-About an hour.
Let it rest for an hour
and then cook it off later.
-What's next?
-We're going to make hummus.
We've got some lemon juice,
garlic, the chickpeas,
tahini paste, extra virgin
olive oil, salt, of course.
So we've made the soy curls.
We got the fries cut.
They've been single fried,
but we go for a double fry.
Oh, yeah.
-This looks exciting.
-Yes.
-That's a mess of jalapeño.
-We're making Zhoug.
Oh, that's
what I was going say.
That's fun to say.
Cilantro, lemon juice, parsley,
fresh garlic, some salt...
-Ton of jalapeños.
-A lot of jalapeños,
Seeds and ribs.
Oh, yeah, that's where
the spice is.
Cumin, coriander, cardamom.
That's like power spice
right there.
Ready to try it?
Love to eat the enamel
off my teeth.
♪♪
[ High-pitched voice ]
It's really nice.
[ Whispers ]
It's nice. It's so good.
Yes.
[ Normal voice ] I'll give you
some time to recover.
Yeah. [ Normal voice ]
No, it's good.
Not overly hot.
Nice balance of the spices
in there --
delicious.
We're making shawarma fries.
Some hummus on there.
We'll add the fries
with the soy curls.
Drop half of it
on the table.
I like how you don't try to
get it in the bowl exactly.
No, I'm not even
trying anymore.
Tahini sauce, amba,
which is pickled mango,
and then,
of course, our zhoug.
Pickled turnips
and jalapeño.
Jalapeño. We pick
all this ourselves.
♪♪
You're getting rich flavors,
you're getting tangy flavors,
you're getting salty flavors,
you're getting spicy flavors.
Soft texture, crunchy texture,
smooth texture.
It's like
an eight set of dice.
It basically it takes you
to Flavortown.
That is absolutely a passport
I mean, that is book stamped.
Dynamite, man.
Shawarma fries.
It's a higher level
of french fry making.
[ Laughs ]
The shawarma meat is vegan,
but they season it really well
to where you wouldn't be able
to tell the difference.
MAN: The hummus is super creamy
and garlicky.
It's exactly
what you're looking for.
Plating the shakshuka.
I think a lot of out-of-towners
are like,
"Vegan's kind of weird,"
but every time
someone comes here,
they're always like,
"Holy moly, this is delicious."
Oh, they make
holy mole here.
I didn't even see that
on the menu. I'll try that.
If I get a craving
for Israeli food,
this is where
I'm going to be coming.
It's amazing.
You got brought up
in unique cultures.
Argentinean, Israeli background,
living in the United States,
all these things combined
start to hone you in
to create dishes that have
this kind of uniqueness.
Like I said, stamp the passport
to Flavortown,
you've just crossed the border.
Coming up, a Logan, Utah,
spot kicking out Cajun Creole.
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa.
Plus, a burger...
That's going to be
mighty juicy.
...with some extra bite.
If you're going to eat a burger,
and you're going to go pass out
in your car,
that's the burger you want.
♪♪
Now, I got to be honest
with you.
I like most of the culinary
trends that go on,
and there was one culinary
trend in particular
that was hitting every
restaurant in every town,
all over the United States.
Then it kind of went away
after the '90s.
I mean, it had big flavor,
creative dishes.
What am I talking about?
Cajun Creole,
but we don't see it
as often anymore.
Why not? Well, it's because
you got to have the attitude.
You got to have the energy.
You got to know the dishes
and you got to have
the background.
I'm here in Logan, Utah. I found
a place that's still rocking it.
This is MayMoes.
Runner, runner, MayMoes doner.
MayMoes is the epitome
of Cajun and Southern cuisine.
Shrimp grilled cheese, boss.
Shrimp grilled cheese.
You got to have
the right people doing it.
Catfish MayMoe needs a home.
The personality brings out
the character of the food
and the spices of the food.
FIERI: That's where Louisiana
transplant
Jason Davis comes in.
I need them dressed nice and
pretty like my old girlfriend.
He left the mortgage business
to open his first joint
where you wouldn't expect it.
You opened the first restaurant
at a gas station?
We did.
On the other end of town.
MAN: When Jason moved from
the gas station to here,
the menu stayed
mostly the same.
I call it
Southern Cajun food.
We bring in whole
alligators, shark.
-Where are they?
-They in the back day.
"They in the back."
A lot of people think
Cajun food is spice.
It's a method, and that's what
we try to convey to the people.
I have blackened chicken pasta.
They smoke this chicken,
and then it's got mushrooms
and peppers
and onions and cheese.
The perfect Cajun seasoning
that Jason makes.
It's only somebody
from Louisiana
that has a cement mixer
that they're going to mix
their own
Cajun blend spice up.
We're going to add salt,
lots of cayenne
if we're for making
Cajun spice, right?
Onion powder, black pepper,
chili pepper, paprika,
granulated garlic.
-Granulated garlic.
-And that's it.
We're going to let that mix
for about five minutes or so.
Okay, good talk.
Now we're going to sear off
our chicken,
about four minutes on each side,
and then we're going to smoke it
for about 40 minutes at 225.
-We're out.
-Little nice bite-sized pieces.
Mushrooms, tomatoes,
green onions.
We start letting it
get warm together.
So you do this pasta dish
off these two little burners?
[ Chuckles ] So when we first
opened at the gas station...
[ Whistles ]
...we did it off one burner.
Going to go ahead
and add our pasta to it.
It's par-cooked, ready to go.
Garlic, Parmesan cheese,
black pepper, heavy cream,
our Creole season
that we made a while ago.
We're going to let
this thicken up.
Top it off with a little bit
of garlic bread,
a little bit of chives
for some color and fun,
and there you go.
♪♪
The smoking of the chicken
is the key.
It really adds a depth.
It's not hot, by any means.
You add just enough cream
to keep it moist
and just enough seasoning
to keep it alive.
♪♪
-Well done.
-Appreciate it.
Two blackened chicken pastas.
The sauce just absorbs
into the pasta
and the spice is incredible.
You just feel warm
when you're done eating it.
Shrimp and grits
coming up right now.
Had you ever had
Cajun Creole food before?
Not like this.
Everyone can find something
they like on the menu.
Bone marrow burger,
hot and ready.
The bone marrow butter burger
is probably my new favorite
item on the menu.
It's a flavor that you've
never experienced before.
-What are we going to make?
-Our butter marrow burger.
Lots of big flavor.
First we're going to add
our beef knuckles.
Has such a ring to it.
And then we're just going
to simply add water, onions.
Simmer for about
an hour and a half.
Once it's strained,
a little bit of butter,
salt, pepper,
cumin, thyme.
-Got it.
-A little more beef flavoring.
This is going to be
our broth for our burgers.
Now we're getting into
some bone marrow.
Yes, sir.
We're going to smoke them
for about 30 minutes or so.
No seasonings on them.
And what kind of pellet
are you using?
Hickory. We're ready to make
our marrow butter.
Soften the butter,
easier said than done.
You were able to get it
on the mixer,
on the bowl, on the stand,
and on the table.
I'm going to practice
getting it on the ground.
You are a hot mess.
Wring them out like that,
and then I'll push through.
Now how many burgers
will this take care of?
Well, we have two pounds
of butter, so three burgers.
No.
[ Laughs ]
If he hadn't laughed,
I was going for it.
We're going to mix it.
Green onions, black pepper.
Roll it up in cellophane.
Pop it in the refrigerator
and you're ready to go.
That's what we use
to top the burger?
-Absolutely.
-Got it.
We're going to make
our house-made burgers.
81/19 by the time
we mixed it up.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You guys don't have 80/20?
No, not in this state.
It's illegal.
-80/20's illegal?
-No.
I bought it. Ah!
[ Laughs ]
We're going to make it
about a 77/43/26.
Hut, hut. Go!
Brisket fat that we've trimmed.
This is the stock
we just made.
Okay. I'll take over the show.
You just go --
No, you've already been
doing that for a while now.
Potato bun, we're just
going to throw it down.
[ Whistles ]
Garlic butter on top of the bun.
Grill season we made.
Get the bone marrow butter
on there,
add the Pepper Jack cheese
on top of that.
This is a Louisiana favorite,
Jambalaya. It's going to be hot.
Horseradish sauce
we make in-house.
Mayonnaise, mustard,
horseradish, and black pepper.
A little bit of lettuce,
a lot of bit tomato, pickle.
There you go,
marrow butter burger.
It's going to be
mighty juicy,
just going to tell you
that right now.
♪♪
You execute
in the finer points.
The bun's great,
the little brush
of the garlic butter's
dynamite.
The bone marrow butter is,
of course, unctuous.
You can't mistake
the richness of bone marrow.
♪♪
If you're going to eat a burger,
and you're going to eat it
at lunch, and you're going
to go pass out in your car,
that's the burger you want.
Well done.
Thank you.
Check those bones
in the smoker real quick.
A lot of people might be
kind of scared of marrow,
but it's just phenomenal.
It just brings
a whole new richness
to an already great burger.
You're going to feel guilty
about it, but you'll come back.
Got a pulled pork po'boy,
table four.
-Sell it.
-How'd you find the place?
He's my neighbor
and he flies us
up here every two weeks?
Every couple weeks. Yeah.
So you fly up here. What do you
come up to Logan for?
-MayMoes.
-Seriously?
That's right.
You fly in here for this?
-Fly in here for lunch.
-I got shrimp and grits.
I like it, man. Well done.
Give it up.
Thank you.
You want the other half
of the burger? Too bad.
So was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for your next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
That's K with classy.
It's classy though.
Two years in the making now,
still hasn't let me down.
Can't beat it.
Wow. Yeah, because you've been
mixing dry spices in it
and not cement, so...
Yeah.
[ Laughing ]