Man, it sure is nice to have
the Camaro home.
It's never here.
That's right.
And, you know,
since we're quarantined --
The car's quarantined.
Now, we've been making
some fantastic meals here
at the Fieri house,
but what do we really want?
I just want
to go out to eat.
Well,
we can't go out to eat,
but we can get takeout,
and I know
some "Triple D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
♪♪
Domenica Catelli is sending
some bomb chicken Parmesan.
Dynamite dish,
perfectly executed.
And then our buddy Bobby the
Butcher from The Tuckaway Tavern
sending us some
crazy Karate Pig Burger.
Outstanding!
Pete from Red Wagon, he's doing
a Cuban-inspired pizza.
That's better
than a Cuban sandwich.
Exactly.
And then we have
Reno from Hawaii.
He's gonna send some ahi.
You want to talk about
having a party at home.
And on top of it all, they're
gonna video-conference in
to give us the true
"Triple D" experience.
You hungry, Hunter?
Very.
Exactly.
This is "Triple D Takeout."
You missed a spot.
Oh, come on.
♪♪
Ha-ha! Look at this
cast of characters.
What's going on, Guy?
Welcome to
this special edition
of "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives Takeout."
How we doing?
How's everybody feeling?
Good.
GUY: Let's start off with
my boy Reno in Hawaii.
Place called Fresh Catch.
For that
Hawaii-Hawaiian time.
The Hawaiian time?
I'm surprised
you showed up, pal.
[ Laughs ]
Pete over at the Red Wagon
in Minneapolis.
Bobby the Butcher all the way
from Tuckaway Tavern.
I've got Hunter working
as my sous-chef and production.
What's up, guys?
Ryder over here
doing our camera.
And I've got all you
characters standing by,
except for
Chef Domenica Catelli
from Catelli's Restaurant
in Geyserville, California,
20 minutes away,
who just dropped off
her dish.
See ya on the video.
So, the whole idea of "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives Takeout"
is the Fieris are
quarantined here at our house.
So we said, "Why don't we call
our favorite 'Triple D' joints
and have them send
some of the dishes
that they're currently working
on, and then we'll eat it?"
Great.
Not a bad deal.
Bobby,
you're up first.
Sure.
And, I'm sorry,
what are the two things
adorning the side
of your screen there?
This one here is the
"Triple D All-Star Tournament"
championship trophy.
Pete, this one might look
familiar, right?
Have you seen that one
before, Pete?
HUNTER: Whoa.
I remember.
And then, over here,
I got the "Triple D Triple G
Tournament" champion,
which I brought
for Domenica.
So, I brought one for
each of them to share today.
[ Laughs ]
That's great.
Where are you at
right now?
Are you at Hop + Grind
or Tuckaway? Where are you?
Right now, I'm at
Hop + Grind in Peabody.
And Tuckaway is
going strong right now.
We turned our attention back
to takeout on the tavern side,
and we're shipping a ton of meat
around the country, fresh.
So, when we went
to Tuckaway,
the one thing
I remember the most
was the gigantic
case of meats --
Wings of
every denomination,
sausages of every concoction,
a monster.
I've never seen anything
like this.
It's a carnivore emporium.
I like that.
#CarnivoreEmporium.
[ Laughter ]
Bobby, how many boxes
did you send us?
Hunter's gonna need
like a handcart.
That's a little sustenance
for you, Chef.
I just want to make sure
you and Hunter and the fam
are getting
enough protein.
Bison tips.
Throw those
right in your wood fire.
They'll be delicious.
Lamb tips.
Oh, dude!
It's like Christmas.
So, what did you actually
send us to cook with?
Some ground
pork shoulder.
I call this dish
the Karate Pig Burger.
Okay.
What we do
at Hop + Grind
is all different funky,
infused patties.
The one I sent you today
is an Asian dumpling burger.
How are we gonna
start this dish?
Grab that pork shoulder
and throw it in a bowl.
Karate Patty Soy Glaze.
That's a soy glaze we make
in house with soy sauce,
pineapple, ginger,
and some black garlic.
Salt and pepper.
Ginger.
Red, crushed chili.
Anything else we're missing?
Small deli containers
should have garlic
and scallions inside.
Alright, so now Hunter
mixes that up by hand?
For sure, yep.
Dojo Sauce -- I've got salt,
cider vinegar, scallions,
black pepper, sambal chili
paste -- sambal oelek.
Yeah, a little heat,
little vinegar.
Roasted garlic,
cayenne pepper -- Wow.
Gotta wake it up a little bit,
you know?
Smoked paprika.
All this together
with this mayo
in, I assume,
food processor?
Yep.
Everybody in the pool.
[ Food processor whirs ]
[ Ding! ]
Yeah, so that sauce is gonna add
that nice salt
and a little bit of heat.
Delicious.
Ooh, yeah, that is good.
I see that you've got
kimchi here.
This is kimchi
you're making?
Yeah, we call that the Quick
Like Ninja Kimchi here at Hop.
Amazing.
Nice little heat to it.
Okay.
GUY: Oh-ho!
Hi.
Look who shows up.
Domenica's here.
HUNTER: Oh!
-Hey, Chef.
-Hi.
Domenica, I timed that.
I think you drove
over the speed limit.
Um...teeny bit.
GUY: Hunter's got the patty
mixed together.
Start that patty
on the flat top?
MARCOTTE: For sure, yep.
Alright, what are
we doing with the buns?
Hit those
with a little butter
and just toast them up
on the flat top.
I like, Bobby, that you call it
a potsticker filling,
because it smells
every bit of that.
Once those buns are toasted,
you're just gonna lay down
a little bit of the Dojo Sauce
and a little bit
of that Soy Glaze
before we put
the burger on top.
Gorgeous.
I don't know who mixed
those burgers, but...
I don't know,
but the burger mixing...
...they did a great job.
...really looks good.
Yeah.
Okay. Next up.
Top those off with that kimchi
I sent you.
A little more Dojo,
little more soy,
and as much fresh cilantro
as you'd like.
Scoot over,
I want to eat.
Get out of my way.
This definitely involves
a hunch on this one.
For sure.
Dynamite, man.
Let's make a burger that's got
a lot of similar flavors.
It would be
in a dumpling filling
that's complemented with
some nice fat from the Dojo.
Let's give a little bit
of sweetness and some soy.
The kimchi
balances it all out.
But, bro,
what you put together here
is a stir fry, Chinese takeout,
all in a burger combo.
We knew that "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives Takeout"
was gonna be crazy.
This just solidified
the entire reason we did this.
Outstanding.
Thank you, Chef.
I mean, like,
shut the front door.
We don't even have one
because we're outside,
but shut something.
Shut the sink door.
[ Door thuds ]
Did you eat
the whole thing?
Mm-hmm.
GUY: Alright, folks,
this is the deal.
We're hanging out at the Fieri
house, out on the patio.
My favorite chefs
have sent me
some "Triple D" specialties
from around the country.
Hunter just ate
the whole burger.
Yeah.
He's gonna need
to take a nap.
We'll see you
in a bit.
You're not
gonna take a nap.
You're gonna start
cleaning this up...
No, no, no.
...because we got
someone else
gonna cook
in a second.
And I'm gonna take this inside
for Mom.
Be right back.
That was amazing.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D Takeout."
Hanging out here
at the Fieri house.
We've got Ryder
on the camera,
Hunter on production
and sous-cheffing,
and I've invited
some of my favorite
"Triple D" chefs
from around the country
to show up here
on a video conference,
but to also send us
great food,
because we're done just cooking
by ourselves in the house.
Yeah.
So, we just had
Bobby the Butcher
all the way from Tuckaway Tavern
and Hop + Grind,
and he sent
this fantastic...
Was it Karate Pig?
The Karate Pig Burger.
-Karate Pig.
-Yeah.
So, over
the commercial break,
we were asleep
by the pool.
I've got Reno from Hawaii,
Pete at Red Wagon.
But without further ado,
Chef Domenica Catelli,
who is in Geyserville,
which is like --
We're here
in Windsor...
It's like
15 minutes.
...so it's like
15 or 20 minutes.
So, she drove it down
versus shipping it.
Domenica is my sister
from another mister.
Anytime I call her for help
when we're feeding people,
Domenica will be blowing
my phone up, saying,
"I know you're doing
something good right now,
and I'm coming to help,
so you just let me in."
Give us a rundown of
what's happening at Catelli's.
DOMENICA: We went strictly
takeout and delivery,
and we had to lay off our staff.
So besides a few managers
and my brother and I,
we have been doing
the whole thing on our own.
Domenica's brother,
Nick,
used to work for me
as a dishwasher.
Your dad still owes me
for giving you that job.
That's Nick's dad
right there.
Nick and Domenica took over
the family's restaurant
that they'd been running
for so many years,
and we had a fantastic
"Triple D" visit there...
[ German accent ]
Right there.
Wow.
You been working out?
Yes, I have.
Just on that arm, though.
Tell me
what you think.
You're a superstar.
Domenica and Nick
have come and competed
on "Guy's Grocery Games"
and won.
Where's your trophy?
Ta-da.
DOMENICA: Right there.
I'm coming for you
next, Bobby.
I'll be here.
[ Guy laughs ]
GUY: What's
the rundown here?
DOMENICA:
Chicken Parmesan
coated in
a light panko breading,
organic tomato sauce,
over smoky, creamy polenta.
Finished with
burrata cheese.
Domenica, red sauce,
smoked mozz.
I think this must be
the ice cream.
Mascarpone.
I'm sorry, you're sending
pictures of your brother
on top
of the containers?
I don't know how that
got in there.
This is very scary.
How do you want this
to go together?
So, you're gonna put
the panko,
and then you're gonna put
the garlic and the salt...
Is that Nick the pterodactyl
in the back?
[ Chuckles ]
Yes.
Catelli, you know that we're
putting this on air, right?
Yeah, yeah,
absolutely.
These are the pictures
that your sister sent us.
I wanted you to feel like
I was there with you.
Thank you. Domenica, all this
granulated garlic in the panko?
Do half of it.
Half of the kosher?
Yep. And then salt and pepper
and the flour.
What else
do we got here?
So, then you have
your egg wash.
You're gonna
stir those up.
Tell me about these chicken
breasts that you sent me,
because
they look fantastic.
We take the full-sized
chicken breasts,
and we slice it and
kind of butterfly it open.
We marinate it overnight just
with a simple -- olive oil,
garlic, basil,
salt and pepper.
Take it through the flour
to the egg,
and then
into the panko mix.
Nice and light and crunchy
and crispy.
So, I've got oil going
at 350.
So, while Hunter's
getting ready to fry those,
tell me about
the polenta.
This is our smoky,
creamy polenta,
and now you're gonna add
smoked mozz.
Okay.
And then we have Parmesan
and mascarpone.
So, you want it to be
nice and creamy, Hunter.
Take a look at those.
Awesome.
Is that right?
-Yep, yep.
-Looks fantastic.
Alright,
what's my next step?
Now I want you to take
the cast-iron skillet
and put polenta in it.
Then you're gonna put the
chicken on top of the polenta.
Then you're gonna put
the tomato sauce on it.
Now, is this the same red sauce
that we made
when we did
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"?
Yes. You're gonna put
burrata over the top,
couple tablespoons
per piece.
We added a whole cup.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah,
we went a little heavy.
You're gonna pop it
into the oven.
Okay.
Into the oven it goes.
We'll clean this up,
you guys come back.
I know this dish
is gonna taste amazing,
and then you'll
be calling Domenica.
See you in a bit.
"Triple D Takeout."
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D Takeout."
Hanging out
in the Fieris' backyard.
And some of our favorite
"Triple D" chefs
from around the country have
sent in great food.
We've got Pete at Red Wagon,
Reno all the way from Hawaii,
and Bobby from Tuckaway,
and Domenica Catelli
from Catelli's Restaurant
in Geyserville, California.
Domenica just delivered
this fantastic chicken Parmesan.
I mean, I got to be honest
with you.
What we're getting ready to eat
is gonna be amazing.
Look at this.
So, burrata on top.
Domenica's
famous red sauce.
DOMENICA: How's it?
Ryder doesn't want
to be on camera
and wants to just be in charge
of running the cameras
until the food
shows up.
[ Chuckles ]
This little
fresh-herb kick
at the base of this whole thing
just pops.
The marination
on the chicken
combined with the ridiculous
amount of creamy goodness,
and the texture of that polenta,
I love it.
Dynamite dish.
Thank you.
Perfectly executed.
Catelli, you rock.
Nicely done.
-Thank you.
Okay.
Reno, in Hawaii.
Now, Reno, where are you
right now, brother?
I am at the Kaneohe restaurant
towards the North Shore.
Give me the breakdown
on the restaurant scene
in Oahu right now.
Maybe half of the island is
closed, as far as restaurant.
Thank God we have our takeouts
doing poke, big lunches.
I just opened up
three new lunch trucks
just so I can push it out
to the community.
All I know -- I show up
at this poke joint,
this place called
Fresh Catch,
and I meet this character who's
giving me a real hard time.
[ Humming menacingly ]
Holy tuna!
And next thing I know is
we're smoking octopus
in a filing cabinet out in
the middle of the parking lot.
Come here.
We have got
some aluminum siding.
I think he cut the hole
in here with a hatchet.
HENRIQUES: In Hawaii,
this is how we do it.
This is old-school style.
GUY: Alright, Reno, what's in
this big box of trouble
that you're bringing?
HENRIQUES:
I ship you everything,
all your favorites
from Hawaii.
Ahi.
More ahi?
More ahi.
[ Laughs ]
How big
was this fish?
That was a 60-pound ahi.
And then we've got about
six different sauces
for you to try for your little
poke party over there.
[ Chuckles ]
What are we making?
One of our most popular dishes
is the ahi katsu.
We're also gonna make
one of your favorite pokes,
ahi limu.
How thick of steaks
are we cutting this into?
It's gonna be about
a 1/4-inch-size steak.
Alright, so, Hunter's
setting up a dredging station.
What'd you send us?
You sent us seasoned flour.
Salt, pepper,
and Japanese panko.
You know, since I'm
the chicken farmer,
we've got that
fresh island egg.
Now, Reno, we're gonna
pan-fry this?
We deep-fry it.
Got it.
While Hunter's
working on the fish,
what's the poke
I want to make?
You're gonna get
the ahi cubed.
You'll put your
dry ingredients first,
so you'll do
the Hawaiian sea salt.
How much
of the kukui nut?
Like a tablespoon.
And then you add in chili pepper
water and then sesame oil.
Sweet onion.
Seaweed now?
A couple sprinkles, yeah.
Green onions.
The best is to make this
and serve this, right?
You eat it right now,
my man.
It kind of looks
like the deli case.
It looks better.
That fish
is so gorgeous!
♪♪
Where you going?
Goodbye.
[ Laughs ]
Success!
The best part
about this,
it's when you get that salt
wrapping around the fish
and the kukui nut's
still crunchy,
and the onion's
still there,
and the fish is still so cold,
it's like from-the-ocean cold.
Lights out.
We haven't even tried this yet.
Are you done?
Oh, that's, like,
a beautiful sear right there.
Good job, Hunter.
Thank you.
So, what's gonna go
on this, Reno?
Aioli sauce,
then the furikake.
And if you
like it spicy,
you can put that
spicy sauce on top.
Oh, we'll do it
spicy.
So, if you want to make
real-deal poke,
you have all of this
that people can buy.
All you gotta do is get
the fresh fish of your choice.
And you also
ship them?
Correct.
And we also ship our fish, too.
And you'll ship
the fish?
So, everything
we just got,
you could ship
to somebody in Wisconsin?
Just gotta pay for
that shipping. We got you.
This is the Black Magic here.
I want to try it with that.
♪♪
You've got to try it
with the Black Magic!
[ Chuckles ]
I just want everybody at home
to see this.
Just a little
breading on that.
Super nice and tender
and raw right inside.
And Hunter
cooked it perfectly.
Oh!
But, Reno, dynamite.
GUY: I'll tell you what --
You want to talk about
having a party at home,
and this is why we're trying
to remind everybody
and we're trying to support
restaurants any way we can.
So, doing the takeout,
doing the delivery, awesome.
But if you're interested in
helping the restaurant employees
in the country,
you'll see these shirts, RERF.
This is Restaurant Employee
Relief Fund.
Visit this website.
We're taking a lot of donations.
And through this foundation,
we're giving $500 grants
to employees without jobs.
Listen, any way you can
support restaurants...
And don't go anywhere,
because,
last but not least, our buddy
doing some real-deal pizza.
See you in a bit.
Reno, you rock.
Nice job.
♪♪
-Get her, buddy.
-Come on!
Hey! Welcome back
to "Triple D Takeout."
Fieri boys here,
locked down in quarantine,
just like you are.
And we are done
with the Fieri favorites.
We're done cooking
for ourselves.
We wanted some takeout,
so we called some of
our favorite "Triple D" chefs
from around the country,
and, boy, did they deliver.
We had Bobby from Tuckaway,
Domenica Catelli from Catelli's,
right down the street,
then we had our boy Reno
all the way from Hawaii,
and that leaves us
going back to Minneapolis.
Pete at Red Wagon,
how are things?
CAMPBELL:
Things are good.
We've been trying to focus
on offering pizza kits
that we can send out
through our website.
GUY:
Now, wait a second.
Do you have a team of elves
working in the back?
We've got about
2,400 pizza boxes a week
that we're going through,
up from about 400.
-I love it.
-See ya!
Thank you.
What is
on the menu?
Let me get the box.
Gentlemen?
The box, the box.
There we go.
Don't go so fast!
♪♪
While Hunter's unpacking this,
give me a little rundown.
I mean, how long ago was it
that we were at Red Wagon?
We were at Red Wagon
in 2016.
Yoooooo!
I think
we might be cousins.
There you go,
Red Wagon pizza.
It's dynamite.
It's an artisan pizza, man.
Everybody at home
right now is going,
"Oh, I want a bite
of that pizza."
You're a gangster.
What up...
Dawg?
[ Laughter ]
Alright, so, give us
a rundown here.
CAMPBELL: So, you've got
some Cuban pork in there.
I sent you dough
that left here frozen.
That'll probably be a little bit
easier to work today.
So, in case the dough
didn't survive,
you sent us yeast and flour
so we could make our own dough?
You got it!
It looks like I'm making
a Cuban sandwich.
Yeah, well, you're making
Carl "The Cuban" Pizza
to dedicate
to my Flavortown mentor.
Back in 2016, when I was
on "Grocery Games," I met Carl.
He quickly became a mentor.
Pete, the calamari's good,
I like it.
To this day, there he is
over the line, looking over us.
HUNTER: Nice.
Beautiful dough,
nice and tight,
even though it was
shipped cross-country.
So, first, you want to lay down
some olive oil.
Open that bag of 50/50
mozzarella/ provolone blend.
Just take a fistful out.
Open up that Cuban pork.
You roasted the pork?
Yep, braised the pork butt
for 12 hours
after it marinates for 24.
So, just breaking off
the little bits.
It'll start to cook down
and render out
some of that fat
onto the pizza, correct?
Exactly.
Let me check the fire
on the pizza oven.
Hunter, shaved ham -- Create,
like, little kind of florets.
So, do you want
this whole thing
turning into a little floret,
like this?
Bingo.
Alright, now you pop that baby
in the oven.
What's your oven
rocking at right now, Guy?
We're about 650,
maybe 700.
Perfect.
Alright, Hunter's
about ready on the pie.
Hunter,
let's see it.
Look at that.
Hang on a second.
I want you to take a look
at this thing.
Look at how great that crust is,
that holds right like that.
Looks gorgeous.
What's our next move here, Pete?
You're gonna cut it
into eighths.
Alright, what's going on here
with this mayonnaise?
That's actually
a mustard-mayo mix.
Just swirl it on.
And then the pickles on top.
I like that the pickles
aren't on too early.
Look at that crust.
Refreshing pickle.
Great cookery there, Hunter.
Killed it, Chef.
That's better than
a Cuban sandwich.
Exactly.
Here's what
I'll say to you, Pete.
One...
thank you for the homage to
my brother -- our brother.
Two, this is just as bold
and as outrageous as Carl was.
We're gonna take the traditional
Cuban sandwich ingredients
and make it work.
A really good touch
of the roasted pork,
a little bit of ham,
that fat, a luxurious,
unctuous silkiness on the pie.
I dig that if you're gonna
take a pizza, my friend,
and you're gonna
break all the rules,
you should name it after the
number-one rule breaker himself,
Carl "The Cuban" Ruiz.
Outrageous.
Spot on. Delicious.
Thank you, Chef.
I am so food coma'd out.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Fantastic dishes.
But I will say this --
We're gonna decide
who has the best
"Triple D Takeout" dish
of today.
So, give me a second.
I'm going to confer.
HENRIQUES: Bobby cannot
win this one.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, come on, guys.
He's got
enough trophies, Guy.
Well, we've got good news,
we've got bad news.
One chef will win
and three will not.
[ Laughter ]
Unless, as Ryder said, you all
move on to the next round!
Send us more food
tomorrow!
[ Laughter ]
So, for the best dish,
we will give $500
in your name to RERF,
which is the Restaurant Employee
Relief Fund,
which you can go to
on the website of rerf.us.
And that $500 donation
will be made in the name of...
[ Drumming ]
Oh, yeah!
♪♪
Boom!
Pete at Red Wagon Pizza.
-Whoa!
-Congratulations.
It was an upset!
You are our winner.
Nicely done.
-Good job, Pete.
-Thanks, Bobby.
At least it wasn't you, Bobby.
I would have been...
[ Laughter ]
Although we should name it
in all of your honor,
because you guys
knocked this out of the park.
This was one of the best
"Triple D"s I've ever had.
I wish you the best. We're gonna
get through this together,
and we'll see you
on the road soon
on "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives."
Thank you, guys.
Take care.
Adios.
Thank you.
Here we go.
Five, four, three, two...
[ Laughing ]
I think there's
something wrong with you.
[ Laughs ]