You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy. That one joint
you checked out in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple-D.'
How are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because "Triple-D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking.
[ Engine revs ]
Like on this trip...
Hey, hey.
...in Baltimore, an Italian
market making memories...
Couldn't forget you, man.
...with their
scratch-made mozz...
I'm de-blinging
'cause I'm in this, dude.
...and authentic arancini.
It is a risotto grenade.
Plus a bistro in Park City
putting some funk
into Flavortown...
MAN:
Chicken bowl with rice.
That's one
of the weirdest dishes
I've ever seen on "Triple-D."
...with your chow-down-worthy
cioppino.
I can't wait to eat it.
So quit talking to me!
[ Laughs ]
And a Cleveland joint keeping
the Italian cuisine coming...
You got to have the pie.
Pizza!
...for a third generation.
They're actually better
than my great grandma's.
Oh, geez. Stop.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D" Nation.
♪♪
I love cooking Italian.
Perfectly cooked
on the bottom.
I love eating Italian.
Mmm!
And I love talking about
cooking and eating Italian.
A little crispy on top.
And in 2008, I found a market
that shared my passion.
Now I'm back.
So I'm in Baltimore.
What do I want to do?
Check out one of my favorite
Italian delis, DiPasquale's.
♪♪
Baltimore is very lucky
to have a place
where customers can come
and feel like they have
an experience in Italy.
MAN: I remember when "Triple-D"
came here to DiPasquale's.
We were all really excited.
It really put this place
on the map.
FIERI:
Well, Joe and Sabrina DiPasquale
had a little something
to do with it
when they started selling
their cultural cooking
out of the back
of their Italian market.
JOE: It started with,
"Make me a sandwich."
So then we brought a table
out into the store.
-There you go.
-Not only can they shop,
they get a bite.
I would shop here
at least once a week.
I don't know how I'm going
to get this all in the car.
[ Laughter ]
Long time.
-Long time no see.
-Good seeing you.
-How are ya?
-Okay, so give me the rundown.
-What's it been?
-2008.
One of the things I loved
is when I walked in,
I could smell it -- the sausage,
the pasta, the fresh mozzarella.
How many pounds of mozzarella
do you guys make a week?
200 pounds.
Just a little more than me.
I don't make any.
I'm de-blinging
because I'm in this, dude.
I think you just
take this off...
There's all the jewelry.
There's no way.
It's scalding hot water.
I -- I don't do this
for everybody.
Okay.
Starting off with the curds.
Submerge.
No salt or anything
in this, right?
Just regular hot water.
-Yes.
-Look at that.
Make sure all the lumps
are out.
♪♪
[ Whistling ]
That was hot.
A little fair warning on that
one would have been nice.
We want to eventually
get it to a ball.
Cover them, and they sit
in here for about 40 minutes.
And then we eat them?
Then we eat.
So tell me what's going on.
What do we got?
We have
a new rice ball there.
It's not a rice ball.
It's arancini.
Come on. I've had to educate
the country on this.
Are we going to fry these
or bake 'em?
-We're going to fry them.
-Ahh! My favorite word.
-Fry.
-No. Ahh!
We're using Arborio rice,
which is a nice, big,
thick, short-grain rice.
Great to work with
when you're making
some kind of rice balls,
easy to mold.
Now, are we doing
this traditional style?
-Yes.
-I'm learning it the right way?
Yes. Grab some rice there.
Make a little ball.
-A little?
Now we're going to
press down on it,
make, like, a little
well in there.
My well of friendship
there.
Sure. We're going to grab
a little bit
of this ground meat.
A little mozzarella.
Now we're gonna
bring the top over.
So that gets buried
in the center.
Then you're gonna dip it
in your little flour and water.
Then into the breadcrumbs,
350-degree oil?
Yes.
Just till they're nice
and golden brown.
Which one you like?
I think that one's perfect.
Okay. [ Chuckles ]
Look at that. That is beautiful.
Pour a little sauce
over it.
Mmm!
If I was taught
how to make those at home,
I never would have
left home.
[ Laughs ]
Winner, winner,
rice ball dinner.
How many arancinis
do you sell a week?
Since you came?
Probably a couple hundred.
-What?!
-Couple hundred.
But before you came,
it was about maybe a dozen.
We're shipping these things
all over.
-Seriously?!
-Yes. You put them on the map.
So we created
a couple new ones.
What do we have in it?
Shrimp and crab.
I want everybody
to understand.
It's a very delicious item,
but it's labor intensive.
You got to make the rice
correctly.
You have stuffing.
You roll it.
You bread it. Your got to
fry it the right way.
There's all these
little components
that go along with it.
So it's not just
some simple little thing.
And the fact that you're now
doing a few hundred,
I kind of apologize.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Mmm. It's delicious.
The arancini's as good
as I remember it.
It is a risotto grenade.
Mmm.
What else?
Our seafood cioppino
is a combination
of sauce, pasta
and six different seafoods.
First,
some cipollini onion.
Add some fresh garlic,
add fennel,
hot pepper, and celery,
a little fresh basil,
Sicilian sea salt,
and saffron.
A little bit of white wine,
tomato puree,
and our house-made
shrimp stock.
Let that simmer down
a little bit.
Then we're going to add calamari
and shrimp, cod,
little neck clams,
and some mussels.
Let that simmer.
And then we're going to start
with our thin-cut pasta.
Place it in the bowl.
Top it with our cioppino stew.
Two cioppino, table 84.
The seafood is fresh.
The sauce is not too heavy.
You really get
a good strong taste
of the individual
seafood components
without being overpowered.
It's delicious.
The pasta's a nice al dente
with a great source.
Little bit of wine.
You can feel it in there.
One of my favorites
when I come in.
When you come in,
by the way,
tell 'em where you
learned about 'em.
When Guy left,
he said, "Get ready.
'Cause it's going to
change your life."
[ Ding! ]
FIERI:
Coming up, I wasn't lying...
Huh?
People started
flooding in.
...and their lights-out
lasagna...
You are the real deal.
...is getting
a brand-new look.
We had to do a spin off.
♪♪
With a name like Guy Fieri,
you know I love Italian food.
If you find yourself
in Baltimore
and you're looking
for some good Italian,
check out this -- DiPasquale's.
Porchetta is on its way.
And I first set this place
up back in 2008.
So what's next?
Well, looks like you're gonna
have a little snack.
-Oh.
-[ Laughs ]
-You want some bread?
-No, I'm good.
-Good.
-[ Laughs ]
This is going to
be the beginning
of a great relationship.
So, since "Triple-D"
has been here,
we have a new marketplace
at Harborview Drive.
We also have doubled
our staff here
at DiPasquale's Highlandtown.
We are busy every day
of the week.
Let it bloom,
and then boom!
FIERI: It really feels like
you're flourishing in here.
-Yeah.
-You are the real deal.
JOE: People started flooding in
for the arancini, mozzarellas,
and the lasagna.
Yeah, the lasagna's huge.
♪♪
Okay. We're gonna make some
pasta sheets for our lasagna.
FIERI:
Pound of flour, five eggs,
a little salt,
and a lot of love.
We're gonna quarter this.
Knead them down a little bit.
-Let me play.
-Okay.
Not too wide.
Not folded into itself.
Back to the press.
Seven times just to get us
to this stage,
then we'll use a little
salted boiled water.
A little bit of olive oil.
Give it about two minutes.
I'm just going to
grease the pan a little bit
with some butter,
then a bit of marinara.
Look at the color on that.
Mm!
Go over to
our pasta sheets.
Look. Ahh!
-Lay it down in here.
-Right.
And you overlap it because
that helps it stay together
when you come out
with the spatula.
A little bit of sauce.
Parmigiano first.
Ground beef.
A little garlic,
a little salt and pepper.
Parsley.
Mozzarella.
And then we're gonna go for
the ricotta cheese.
Nice and light.
Mm-hmm.
How many layers of this,
three?
Three should work.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, look at that!
♪♪
See those layers in there?
Ohh!
Mmm.
That's delicious.
That's up there with any of
the best lasagnas there are.
-Great job.
-Thank you.
MAN: Meat lasagna ready.
We had a huge spike
from lasagna.
And we had to do a spin-off.
This is our
eggplant lasagna.
We're gonna start by coating
the pan with butter,
butter and breadcrumb
will help the lasagna not stick.
Add the baked eggplant.
Add some of the marinara,
a little bit of the mozzarella,
and the Parmigiano-Reggiano
sauce.
We're gonna add a little bit of
egg wash that has fresh parsley,
basil, salt, and pepper.
And then we add exactly
the same layers.
And a nice breadcrumb
topping.
Bake it for about
an hour and a half.
♪♪
Eggplant lasagna,
table seven.
The eggplant is one of
my favorite go-to dishes.
It's huge. I probably gonna have
to take a nap after this one.
It's fantastic.
You can taste the saltiness
from the Reggiano,
very authentic,
very Italian.
Can't make it to Italy?
Come to DiPasquale's.
I think you'll get a nice
little Italian immersion.
I'm glad you remember us.
I mean, it's nice.
Couldn't forget you, man.
You're good people making
great food --
or should it be "great people
making great food."
You agree?
Of course you do.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
a ski town spot in Utah...
Were you snowed in
when you made this?
We were doing something.
...taking comfort food...
You take that quick right,
you end up over
in Funky Flavortown.
...into a new comfort zone.
If I came back here,
I'd have this again.
♪♪
I'm here in Prospect Square
in Park City, Utah.
And I'm right
in the thick of things.
Back in 2014,
I popped into this place
cranking out what I like to call
funky comfort.
Anything you order
will be amazing.
And thankfully,
nothing's changed.
Boneless wings,
table four.
This is Sammy's Bistro.
What we saw in "Triple-D" was
exactly what we got
when we walked in the door.
MAN: There's nothing on
the menu that I've ever had
that I didn't absolutely love.
That's because chef and owner
Sam Harris
took his fearlessness
off the slopes
and brought it into the kitchen.
Do you ski?
Do you board?
Oh, I'm a skier.
I think media moguls back
in the day.
Hence the...?
Yeah.
When I was younger,
we got done skiing
and I'd cook for my friends.
It's a lot
of experimentation.
Just throw something together.
Sometimes it turns out.
So this one is one of those.
This is
a savory chicken bowl.
Show me what you got.
A little canola oil.
Poblano.
Onions,
put a little garlic in,
and then the chicken,
and then coat it with spices.
Yellow curry,
garam masala,
paprika,
onion powder,
salt.
And a little
black pepper.
Get the spices coating
the chicken,
and then just hit
some water on top.
Let it simmer
two to three hours.
Until it's super tender.
Now we're going
to make...?
Tomatillo aioli.
Hit it.
It's not a traditional aioli,
but that's what we call it.
Hey, it's your house, man.
You can call it
the Easter Bunny.
Tomatillos, cilantro,
buttermilk, jalapeño.
The little engine
that could, huh?
Makes it happen.
Pro. Look at that.
I'm going to throw a little
bit of lime juice in there
and our house Cajun seasoning.
The hits keep coming.
Ranch dressing mix.
Were you snowed in
when you made this?
We were doing something.
It was late night.
Yeah, it was fun.
Now we put the bowl
together?
Yep. Jasmine rice.
We ladle our chicken.
Some of the tortilla
strips on top.
Make it tall, tall, like
your hair.
Looking good.
Cilantro, and finish off
with the tomatillo aioli.
That's one of
the weirdest dishes
I've ever seen
on "Triple-D."
Well, Flavortown --
You've been to Flavortown?
Every night.
Sometimes on your way
to Flavortown,
if you take
that quick right,
you end up over
in Funky Flavortown.
It's a sister city.
That might be where we are.
Just one more exit,
actually.
[ Chuckling ]
One more exit.
♪♪
Chicken's super tender.
Comfort food at its finest.
It is funky comfort.
I will give you that, brother.
Mmm! I would,
without question,
if I came back here,
I'd have this again.
The menu
is pretty eclectic.
It's something that pretty
much appeals to everyone.
One of the things I love
about Sammy's is there are lots
of options for me, like
the vegan coconut red curry.
So to make the vegan coconut
red curry,
we started with sautéing
minced garlic and minced ginger,
add crushed tomatoes,
garam masala, turmeric,
paprika, kosher salt, cumin,
and cayenne.
We let that cook
for about an hour
and blend it until very smooth.
And at this point,
we're gonna add our vegetables.
Red bell pepper, zucchini,
eggplant,
yellow onions, and carrots.
Let that simmer
for another 45 minutes.
And then we add
the coconut milk,
which gives it
a nice creaminess.
And then coconut oil.
We plate it over jasmine rice,
put a little side
of pita bread on there
and garnish it with green onion.
Coconut red curry.
This is outstanding.
The vegetables are so hearty.
It almost taste like
there's meat in there.
It's spicy,
but not too spicy.
It's incredibly rich
and flavorful, filling.
Love all the veggies.
Now what are we making?
The Chivito club
sandwich.
The who club?
The Chivito club.
We're going to make
the marinade
for the pork tenderloin --
canola oil,
soy sauce, garlic, ginger,
cilantro, lime juice.
How long is this tenderloin
going to marinate?
45 to an hour.
Grill it.
Yeah, medium,
and let it rest for a minute.
While we do that, we're
gonna make the egg.
♪♪
Hey, hey!
He'll be here
all week, folks.
And it's on a hoagie roll.
A little bit
of the tomatillo aioli.
Lettuce, tomato, pork tenderloin
a little bit of bacon,
and some spicy mayo.
♪♪
All right.
And the egg.
I went to grab the egg,
and I turned around,
and the egg was missing.
♪♪
Huh?
[ Chuckles ]
Where's the egg?
It looks good.
Let's have it.
It's perfect now,
right?
We know he loves eggs.
There it is.
Throw a little fried egg on top.
A little more
tomatillo aioli.
♪♪
Mmm. Even with egg on there,
it's a great sandwich.
Mmm.
Before
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
it was like 20th or 25th on
the list of most popular things.
It's like number two now.
And I have a feeling
that in a couple years,
the seafood cioppino will be
one of the top-selling things
on the menu, as well.
This may be my new go-to,
the seafood cioppino.
We throw red onion
and garlic in,
and let that sauté
for a few minutes.
After that, we reduced
some merlot red wine down,
and then we add
our crushed tomato,
oregano, basil,
a little bit of sugar,
balsamic vinegar,
and salt and pepper.
Add a little bit
of garlic, shrimp,
scallops, and the mussels,
little neck clams, calamari,
and mahimahi,
a little white wine
and water,
and our house-made marinara.
Fennel bulb -- a little bit
of a licorice flavor,
butter, and we finish it off
with some chipotle
to give it
a little bit of a kick.
Just cover that
and let it steam.
Plate it over Jasmine rice.
Seafood cioppino,
table eight.
Really tasty,
and it's got this chipotle
that pops when you eat it.
Not over the top,
but definitely excellent flavor.
I can't wait to eat it,
so quit talking to me!
[ Laughs ]
SAM: Once Guy comes in,
you're on the map.
Next thing you know,
line out the door.
Unbelievable.
We're going to open another
place out at Kimball Junction
called Sammy's Bistro Express.
Should be really cool.
Watch out for this guy.
When you see him on the slopes,
if he skis like he cooks,
take a day off.
♪♪
Now coming up, an Italian family
bringing their classics...
I'm a meatball aficionado,
you know that.
...to the crowds
all over Cleveland.
Chicken Parm, pick up.
-Nice job.
-Thanks.
FIERI: I've always had
a hard time turning down pizza,
so that's why here
on "Triple-D,"
every time I get a chance
to try the pie, I am there.
And back in 2009,
it was no different.
So I found myself
on the east side of Cleveland
at an Italian joint
that's been around since 1956.
Have you worked here
all your life?
Since I've been
2 years old.
No kidding.
Now they're on their third
branch of the family tree.
This is Geraci's.
♪♪
Meatballs. Pick up.
The food's always top notch.
MAN:
"Triple-D" Let the world know
everything that we already know
about the Geraci's.
It's a great family restaurant
run by a great family, as well.
You have Marti, Greg, Buck,
Pat, and Maggie.
FIERI: But it all started back
in 1956 with Michael and Fran.
-Veal Parm.
-She's 87?
She's 87. He's 90.
-Wow!
-We're still here.
My wife and I.
And when I was there in 2009,
their daughter Fran
was also helping out.
You know what
I got to have now.
Pizza!
You got to have the pie!
See, everybody
has their own style.
I'm into [whistling]
And I like my sauce
all the way to the edge.
Yeah. Okay. Now we're going to
take some mozzarella cheese.
This is Margherita pepperoni,
stick them into the oven.
550. Come around me.
What, are we gonna dance now?
Okay. Now stop that.
How long is it gonna take
to cook?
Seven, eight minutes.
-Look at those pies.
-Yeah.
[ Crust crunches ]
This thing sounds like
an ice breaker
on a ship in Alaska.
Mmm. That pepperoni
is ridiculous.
I think the way I would
describe that pie the best
is to say it's
really fresh.
-Thank you.
-Mmm.
Now, I don't know
if you know this,
but the rest of the country,
when they get to be 87 and 90,
usually retire.
-It's our social.
-This is also your party?
-Right.
My parents built
a great restaurant,
and they both
work really hard.
Sadly, Michael and Fran
are no longer with us.
But their other daughter Marti,
and her husband, Greg,
are keeping the party going.
Now, where do the recipes
come from, Fran?
-My mom.
-And your mom got 'em from?
-Her mother.
-So we have generations
of recipes going on here?
Right.
Another one of our classic
dishes is our chicken Parmesan.
We pound out
a chicken breast.
We put a very nice
breading on it,
and then we sauté it
till it's golden brown.
We add a little bit
of our Geraci's sauce.
Let's recap this sauce --
Sweat the onion.
A little bit of sugar
in this.
And salt, oregano, basil,
Stanislaus tomatoes.
GREG: We add some cheese
and melt it golden brown,
and it's ready to go.
Chicken Parmesan
is unbelievable.
The chicken is extremely moist.
It's fresh.
Perfect amount
the Parmesan cheese.
My personal favorite
is the Geraci's sauce.
There's so many
different flavors.
They have it on
a lot of their dishes.
MAN: They put the Geraci's sauce
on the lasagna.
It's really good.
One of our number-one sellers
is our lasagna.
We start off
with our signature sauce,
it layer with our lasagna
noodles and our meatballs.
[ Chuckles ]
Start with 10 pounds
of ground beef,
mushed up a little bit.
Five pounds of ground veal
makes these meatballs
nice and tender.
Whisk up these eggs.
There's a dozen in here.
Okay.
Do some salt, pepper.
I am a good breadcrumber
Yes, you are.
Italian parsley.
How about some of that
good amount of cheese
that's going to go in here?
Oh, yes.
Good cheese flavor to this.
Want some agua?
A little bit.
That's good.
Now, how many meatballs
is this gonna make us?
I'd say 25.
What temperature are we gonna
cook these at in the oven?
-450.
-45 minutes to an hour?
-Till they're nice and brown.
-Yeah.
That looks like
meatball madness.
I'm a meatball aficionado.
You know that?
That's good.
Mmm.
That's one of the most
tender meatballs ever tried.
-Nice job.
-Thanks.
MARTI: So then we add ricotta,
Romano, and mozzarella cheese,
and our signature sauce.
We add two more layers like that
and put it in the oven.
Lasagna, order up.
WOMAN: It's made
with their special meatballs,
and it's made in its own dish.
So you get, like, all lasagna
edge all the way around.
It's absolutely delicious.
MAN: It's exactly what you think
lasagna is supposed to be.
They take that and they
multiply it times 100.
I'm sorry, Grandma,
but they've outdone you.
They're actually better
than my great grandma's.
Oh, geez!
Stop!
Since "Triple-D" came to us,
we've really expanded ourselves.
We just opened
a third restaurant.
You don't have to drive quite
as far to get to Geraci's.
A lot of people appreciate that.
So, Fran, Marti, and Toni,
your daughters,
are you confident
that they're gonna carry it on?
I think so.
They should know by now.
-It's gonna be theirs.
-[ Laughs ]
Our children are
the third generation
that are now
working the restaurant.
I think you've made a lot
of people really happy.
I see all the smiles
when folks come in.
MAN: And this is the first place
that I want to show people
because I'm proud of it.
And there's nothing else
that'll do besides Geraci's.
♪♪
One cioppino, for here.
Table eight.
FIERI:
And they're not the only ones
whose customers are lining up
to keep their traditions alive.
Savory chicken bowl
with rice.
Order up.
There are plenty more spots
like them all over the country,
and we'll check them out
next time on "Triple-D Nation."
Let me taste how that's
coming along.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
Nice body with that.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪