So when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks --
-Dad, can we just --
I mean, please go to a
restaurant at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner? Huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got the bomb bologna
coming from some
unforgettable twins in Atlanta.
Look at that.
And George from Krazy Fish
is crazy as ever,
sending us
a one-of-a-kind burger.
Welcome to "The Goodfellas
Cooking Hour." I'm Guy.
My buddy Richard in Miami
is shipping out
some smoked beef dumplings.
It's kind of like an orchestra
of like 100 instruments.
And we've got
the West Virginia characters
from Hillbilly Hot Dogs sending
one of their wild creations.
That's honestly just stupid.
I would take a bath in that.
And on top of it all, they're
gonna video conference in
to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
-I like the way you think.
-Exactly.
This is
"Triple-D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
-What's up, guys?
-Hey, what's up?
Hi. Yee-haw.
-Yee-haw.
Wow. It's gonna be
that kind of day.
It is.
As we know, this is
"Triple-D Takeout."
Ryder's running the cameras.
Hunter is the sous-chef.
And the whole inspiration
of this
started when
we were locked down
and we said, "Well,
we want some delicious food."
Hunter and I were done
cooking for everybody.
And we said, "Well,
let's kind of mix it up a bit."
We've got Krazy Fish
out of North Carolina.
We've got Fox brothers
out of Georgia. There you go.
Sharie from Hillbilly Hot Dogs
in West Virginia.
Is it "La-sage"
or "La-saj?"
-"Lee-sage."
-Lesage.
Of course,
we like to say Le-sausage.
Le-sausage.
"We serve le-sausage
in Lesage."
Le-sausage.
We have Richard from Miami.
Are we doing Black Brick
or Sakaya Kitchen?
We do a Black Brick mixed
with Society BBQ.
We're doing real fusion
for you.
We're gonna need
treadmill tomorrow.
Yeah.
Alright, Sharie,
you're up first.
Hunter, Ryder,
grab the box.
I don't think we've ever seen
anyplace like
Hillbilly Hot Dog
on "Triple-D"
with school buses
that you eat in.
What year was that,
Sharie, that we did that?
2007.
So a lot was going on
on that visit.
Mmm.
They have this bill that they --
[ Bell ringing ]
[ Laughs ]
Yee-haw!
They make a hot dog
called the Homewrecker.
♪ I got
a ho-o-ome-a-wrecker ♪
15 inches long, 1 pound,
all-beef weenie.
There it is.
[ Laughter ]
-Isn't that wonderful?
-Yeah.
♪ Ho-o-mewrecke-e-r ♪
[ Laughs ]
Is this
an original Homewrecker?
That's a home wrecker there.
That's a big hot dog.
-You're really insane.
-Lookit there.
Ding, ding, ding.
-[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
You sent me everything
under the sun here.
What's the menu item?
I sent you our Spank'n Bacon
Hillbilly Harlot.
How are we making it?
In a pan, fry up --
there should be
five slices of bacon.
Alright, so we're gonna
cook this, bake it off.
What does this dish
look like, Sharie?
It looks like a relish
with some rice in it.
Alright,
sauté the peppers and onions,
and the rice is gonna
go on top of this dish?
I use the rice as a binder
because without it,
it's too soupy
for the hot dog.
What's he chopping?
That bacon?
-See, I just tear it up.
-Guy's got to chef it up.
-Yeah.
-Got to do something here.
-Battle of the blonds.
-[ Chuckles ]
Hey, hey!
Got to just make sure
it's good.
Yep.
Hunter's watching me sweat
it out to the oldies over here.
In with that?
-Perfect.
-Now go in with the rice?
-Yep. And your Worcestershire.
And what is this
little concoction you gave me?
Brown sugar, crushed red pepper,
and black pepper.
-Got it.
-Throw in your tomatoes,
cover it up,
and let it simmer a little bit.
Nice and slow.
-How have you expanded
the restaurant
since we were there last?
-We've got a deck up above.
-I love it.
And then we opened up
a wedding chapel.
So we have weenies
and weddings.
Yee-haw!
Do you cut the Homewrecker
afterwards?
Well, yeah.
What kind of hot dog
do we have?
-It's an all-beef.
-Wrapped in bacon.
Double wrapped.
Flash fry about a minute,
a minute and a half,
and then right into the pan
just to finish them off
and give them
that golden touch.
Dynamite. How do you want us
to heat up the buns?
Just toast on top of it.
Yeah, that looks good.
Looks awesome.
We're gonna serve this up.
-Lay that weenie down.
-Sauce over the top.
This is a pretty complicated
we need to put together here.
It's a fancy dog.
Mmm.
-Got him speechless.
-Mmm!
♪♪
That's a next-level weenie
right there.
Whoo-hoo!
I'm gonna try to
break this down for you,
but I don't have enough words
'cause I want to shove this
in my face again.
Yee-haw!
You already can't go wrong
with a bacon-wrapped hot dog,
but this jambalaya rice mix
that we have going on,
that's honestly just stupid.
I would take a bath in that.
Hunter's exactly right.
This hot dog has such great
texture, such great meatiness.
Nice bun. The bun holds up
but doesn't compete.
It just becomes basically
a napkin you can eat.
But this chili sauce, rice,
onion, bacon fat,
cut up bacon, super spice,
it's fantastic.
Thank you.
My sister from another mister,
you have delivered.
Ding, ding, ding.
[ Bell ringing ]
Coming up when we get back,
all the way from Miami Beach
Chef Richard Hales.
Buddy, pressure's on.
Mmm.
♪♪
Welcome back --
"Triple-D Takeout."
Hanging out here in the backyard
with Hunter and Ryder,
getting some awesome deliveries
from some of our favorite
"Triple-D" joints
from around the country.
We've got our buddy George
from Krazy Fish
out of North Carolina,
the Fox brothers in Georgia,
and we just had Sharie
from Hillbilly Hot Dog,
in Lesage, West Virginia.
-Ding, ding, ding.
[ Laughs ]
But not to be outdone,
one of my favorite chefs,
he's got some awesome
restaurants down in Miami.
My brother, Richard Hales.
We met him on "Triple-D."
I bought a Cadillac from him.
I have been on "Triple-D"
with Sakaya.
Welcome to the culinary dojo
in Flavortown
And black brick.
I mean, like,
lights out good.
I can't figure out how to get it
in my face fast enough.
-Now Society BBQ.
-How is Society BBQ doing?
It's doing great.
We've launched our nationwide
mail-order business.
You didn't get brisket
and beef ribs
and these dumplings that
we're doing on the show today.
GUY:
This better be one heck of a box
We're going to open up, pal.
-Oh, yeah.
-Alright, so dumplings.
[ Both laugh ]
-Nobody gives gifts like me.
-[ Laughs ]
Okay, so let me tell everybody
the story.
One day, a buddy of mine calls,
and he says,
"Hey, do you know anything
about Richard Hales
sending a car out here?
I have the coolest
1964 Buick Riviera
sitting here at my shop
that he had delivered.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here's the title.
[ Laughs ]
-It's official.
Whoo! Ding, ding, ding, ding.
[ Bell ringing ]
Dude, you are whacked.
I don't even know what to say.
-Wow.
-Guy's got a tear in his eye.
So, to just get this clear,
we are making a dish
that is on the menu
at Black Brick or BBQ Society?
It is at both. We're doing
smoked beef cheek
from Society BBQ.
I smoke those at two 285 over
white oak for about 3 hours,
and I'm mixing it with my spices
from Black Brick Chinese,
and we're making dumplings
for you.
I sent you whole beef cheeks
and beef cheeks
already process
with no seasoning.
I just want to look at one
for a second
just so everybody can see
what we're talking about.
Beef cheek is actually
a pretty lean cut.
That ain't lean. That's all fat
in the middle of that.
That's a big chunk
of flavor.
That's the best part.
[ Laughs ]
Alright, you want to take the
yellow cooking wine, the garlic.
There's water there that has
Szechwan peppercorns
floating in it
just strain those peppercorns
out of their cumin spice
and the chili bean paste.
Pulse that
and then add scallion.
If we went and hammered this
right now with the scallions,
then we'd beat him up and you
wouldn't even recognize him.
But once that's mixed up,
we'll add in those little
sparkles of scallions,
sparkles of scallions.
-And the sesame oil.
Is this
a 90-ingredient dumpling?
-Yes.
-[ Chuckles ]
He does put a lot
of ingredients,
but, boy,
he is masterful.
It's kind of like an orchestra
of, like, 100 instruments.
I could see you roll these
all out by hand, chef.
You need to do
a crescent moon,
11-fold dumpling.
-Say that twice.
-[ Laughs ]
That's an 11-fold
dumpling right there.
-Ooh. Wow.
-Beautiful.
GUY: We make a lot of dumplings.
I have body by dumpling.
I have made three.
Hunter's made not even one.
Okay, Hunter, want to make
the Alabama sauce?
Mix the mayo,
the cider vinegar, kosher salt,
and your tolerance
of how much cayenne you want,
horseradish.
and then some ground pepper.
Let them get a little bit brown
on the bottom.
Give them
a squirt of water
about quarter way up
the dumpling
and put a lid on it
right away.
Once the water evaporates,
the dumplings are ready.
-How's that looking, Chef?
-Looks good. I love it.
That looks great.
-Hi, Mimi.
-Hi.
My mom just crashed the set.
She can smell that she's got
good dumplings being cooked.
HALES:
The chili oil soy sauce mixture
you can spoon on top.
♪♪
RYDER: Please do not put that
in there.
[ Laughs ]
The Alabama sauce absolutely
is what brings us all together.
-That is fantastic.
-And then here comes
the other one
that can sniff out a good meal.
There's my dad
wandering through the back.
Alright, Dad. It's hot.
-Hi.
There you go.
It's hot, Dad. It's hot.
That's good.
Hey, I like that.
You know my buddy Richard
from Miami.
What's up, buddy?
So this is part of that
to-go thing,
you know, where
you call Miami and they --
yeah,
that's pretty good.
And they just ship it out.
There you go.
You want to take
the last one to Mom?
Mm-hmm. You bet.
You see what this
has turned into?
I tell you something.
Then you call up your favorite
chefs from around the country
and say,
"Hey, ship me a new dish
that you haven't even put
on the menu yet
or something that's, you know,
blowing the doors open,"
and what happens?
We start calling
in all the people
from around the neighborhood,
like my mom and dad.
This is "Triple-D Takeout."
Hales, you rocked it, brother.
Nice job.
Thank you.
Coming up when we get back, our
buddy George from Krazy Fish.
Boy, pressure's on.
See you in a bit.
Okay, I'll arm wrestle you
for the last one.
We're back.
"Triple-D Takeout,"
hanging out here
at the Fieri house.
We have Richard from Miami,
Fox brothers out of Georgia,
Sharie from Hillbilly Hot Dogs,
and then we go over
to Krazy Fish
and they should've just
called it Krazy George.
-Krazy Fish, baby.
-I'm not kidding you.
You guys didn't see it
when we did "Triple-D" there,
when he says crazy,
he means crazy.
Oh!
Welcome to
"The Rocky Balboa Cooking Hour."
PRISCO: Live at Krazy Fish.
Bada bing.
Right there for you.
Yeah,
now you're scaring me.
Real deal.
Crazy but real deal.
Crazy, hey, ho.
We just opened up another
place called Two Buks Saloon.
It's another bar.
-Fantastic.
I don't know what these are.
But I'm impressed.
We stuffed it
with a bunch of stuff for you.
These cards
are beautiful, by the way.
What are these?
Yeah, those are made from
SheOriginals.com,
and we're selling those here
in the restaurant
and were giving all the money
to the Restaurant Association.
Those are beautiful,
man.
The program
that they started with
the National Restaurant
Association
is called R-E-R-F -- Restaurant
Employee Relief Fund --
and we raised over $22 million
for restaurant employees
that lost their job
during the pandemic.
And people still need support.
That is an awesome way to do it.
You do understand
there's an award today,
and it doesn't
involve cash or prizes.
No, Ryder, it involves
just simple bragging rights,
and that's bragging rights
as to who is gonna
get the best dish.
So let's see what Krazy Fish
brought us.
And I like the shades.
-We're making a burger.
We're making a burger,
but you sent me a fish?
I figure
I'd send you a whole fish.
Luca Brasi
swims with the fishes.
Is that what you're doing?
Is there a hit
getting ready to happen?
Am I getting a little -- am
I getting a little "Godfather"?
-It's a red fish.
-George, too much, brother.
Alright,
wow we started this thing?
Alright. You don't
trust him oil on there
so you can start
those potatoes.
And what is the actual name
of the dish?
This is our Krazy Burger
and a burrito.
So we're gonna get
that 81/19 ground beef
with red crushed pepper,
garlic, and onion.
You want some salt
in that meat?
No, no.
No salt in that meat.
No salt in the meat?
-That's crazy.
Get your hands in there deep,
Hunter.
[ Laughs ]
And start cooking that bacon
at the same time.
The meat is mixed,
and the bacon's going down.
What's up next?
-Alright,
you're gonna roll that meat
like a meat loaf log.
You know what I'm saying?
You want it to be
about three to four ounces
'cause it's got to go
in the roadie shell.
In the what-y shell?
In the roadie shell,
the flour tortilla shells.
Once you roll it,
it becomes a roadie.
How does he want
to roll it?
I don't know, dude.
I -- Hunter...
PRISCO: You're gonna make them
about four inches long.
And how do you want
those cooked?
You're gonna
cook them medium.
What's up next?
You're gonna make
the Krazy Sauce.
Okay. So I assume the mayo
is going in the Krazy Sauce.
Don't forget to melt
the butter now.
Sorry.
[ Laughter ]
Yeah, you're gonna throw
the melted butter in there
with the mayo.
You got to add
the rice wine vinegar,
the sugar,
the garlic, paprika.
Welcome to "The Goodfellas
Cooking Hour." I'm Guy.
How's that bacon?
Bacon's good, cooked.
What happens next?
So you're gonna take
that flour tortilla.
Roadie. Oh, now he's speaking --
now he's speaking normal to us.
Throw some bacon
in there,
some lettuce, tomato,
and onion,
sliced jalapeños.
About three slices
of cheese on there.
That's American Swiss
we're using.
You got to tuck it
and roll it.
And you don't put
the potatoes inside of it,
even though it's a roadie?
Now, put them
on the side.
When you're on "Triple-G"
and guys says that,
you put the potatoes inside
or you go home.
Sear it golden brown
on all three sides.
♪♪
Dunk it in Krazy Sauce
and chow down.
♪♪
There's roadie has got
a ton of flavor,
and I love the dipping sauce,
the Krazy Sauce.
That crazy sauce
makes it for sure.
It's rich, it's tangy, it's
zesty, and you're right, man.
This burger rolled up
inside of this with the cheese
and the bacon
and a little bit of the veggie,
a little bit of the crunch,
little bit of freshness from it,
there's no bun competing.
It's just a vessel
to make sure that
this all gets in your mouth.
Delicious.
-That's great.
That right there,
that's Krazy Fish 101.
Alright,
this is not over, folks.
Don't worry. There is one
more surprise package
coming from the Fox brothers
all the way from Georgia,
and we'll see you in a bit.
-Yay!
I'm gonna go lay down
by the pool.
-Sounds good.
-Good talk.
♪♪
Well, welcome back.
We are here hanging out
at the Fieri house.
"Triple-D Takeout."
Hunter, Ryder, Guy.
We have Richard from Miami.
We have Sharie coming in
from West Virginia.
We've got Krazy Fish
out of North Carolina.
But I got to be
honest with you,
I think everybody is
about ready to tap out,
but we can't because we've got
the Fox brothers in Georgia.
I had a fantastic visit there
when I went with my buddy
Rutledge,
and there was a lot of laughs.
I feel like I could just
punch my ticket. to --
what's that city
you always go to?
That's Flavortown 101,
ain't it?
-There you go.
-That's it.
When you're using C.A.B. --
certified Angus beef --
you're starting
with great clay.
I get it.
Yeah, 'cause you love
the movie "Ghost."
I totally get
the pottery reference.
That was a great one, man.
[ Laughter ]
You're really good at this.
Jonathan, Justin, tell me,
what's been happening
over at Fox Bros.?
JONATHAN:
We're right in the middle
of about to start opening
a new restaurant.
9,300 square feet
of space.
-How much?
-9,300.
I got to tell you something,
guys.
I know how great
the food is,
and now to think that you have
just sent us a care package...
Very nice, gentlemen. Thank you.
-He shirts.
-It's not a car.
-Those are sick.
Actually, you know how bad
we need these up at our ranch?
It's a fashion show,
ladies and gentlemen,
-Liking it.
-So we're talking
about everything people
can get online.
Can they buy
all the Fox Bros. rubs?
Oh, yeah.
Sauce, rubs -- everything.
Alright, here we go.
What is this dish?
-Our smoked bologna sandwich.
This isn't
your average bologna.
I could just tell
from all the texture
and particulates in there.
Yeah, so we make it
in-house.
I mean, I figure,
if you're gonna do something,
you might as well
do it right.
It's a pork and beef blend.
Add some more dry rub,
a couple other seasonings
in there.
We'll grind it up
two, three times.
Definitely got smoke.
Got great moisture to it.
How thick do we want it,
'cause I'm gonna
just keep eating it like this
if you don't tell me.
About a quarter to a half-inch,
somewhere right in there.
Griddle it up.
Tell me what
you did on the fries.
They're hand-cut, and then we
blanch them at about 325,
fry them 375
till they're crispy.
That fry seasoning,
it's got our dry rub
and a little bit of sugar
in it.
How's that bologna looking?
-Really good.
Take some of that
Texas toast bread,
and you're gonna butter
that up and toast it.
I've opened up the corn chips,
and I'm eating those
'cause I thought
you wanted me to.
Save some
for the sandwich
And where's the cheese going?
Those are pimento
cheese patties.
Once the bologna's
griddled,
add that pimento cheese
on top of one of the slices
and cover it up
and let it melt.
The sandwich name is
the Carl Ruiz.
You guys named
this after "Cuban"?
The winner of
the championship belt is...
Carl "The Cuban" Ruiz.
Cha-cha-cha-cha-cha-cha!
who we all wear our wristbands,
we all love the Cuban,
and...
We all miss him.
-Carl likes this dish?
-It was his favorite sandwich.
I want to go get
a bologna sandwich now.
So when
that bread's toasted,
you want to take
that barbecue mustard
and throw on each side.
Alright, so bologna
coming over.
Stack it up.
You want to take a big handful
of those corn chips
and smash them on there.
Like you're in third grade,
and you're piling everything
on your sandwich.
Don't forget
those pickles.
Look at that. Huh?
Looks fabulous.
Fabulous. Oh.
-Do the hunch.
-Ah.
That's a bologna dance
right there.
-The walk off.
-Oh, yeah.
That's a good
bologna sandwich there.
That is not
a good bologna sandwich.
I got to be honest with you.
[ Mouth full ] It's not
a good bologna sandwich.
-Exactly.
-[ Laughs ]
This is a phenomenal
bologna sandwich.
It's a bunch of great meat.
Wow.
Great bologna.
Great cheese. Great bread.
JONATHAN:
It's not that bologna sandwich
you grew up with.
That is fantastic.
It's not the bologna sandwich
you grew up with.
It's the idea of it.
-Yeah.
-But then you went
and cheffed it and took it
to a whole 'nother level.
And, guys, whew!
I mean, it is over the top.
-That's awesome.
-Well done, guys.
This is definitely
an elevated bologna sandwich.
And matter of fact,
even call it a bologna sandwich,
I think people go,
"Come on."
And you say, "Wait till you try
the Carl Ruiz."
That's like calling Carl
just a chef.
He was so much more than that.
And that sandwich is so much
more than a bologna sandwich.
So, as you know,
at the end of this show,
we have to give best dish.
There's no cash prizes.
There's only bragging rights.
And I got to say,
everybody brought it.
Let me confer with my judges.
[ Chuckles ]
I do have to confer
with my judges
and give it up to the
Fox brothers and the Carl Ruiz.
-Whoo!
-Fantastic sandwich.
Everybody --
-Good job, guys.
You know what?
America's so excited
that they can call you
and have this shipped
to their house.
We'll see you next week
on "Triple-D Takeout."
Adios.
-Later.
-Killer.
-Take care, guys.
-Ding, ding, ding.
-Ding, ding.
Everybody's a winner.
♪ Sonny's the Weenie Man ♪
♪ He's got a weenie van ♪
-♪ He owns a weenie stand ♪
♪ He sells
the best weenies around ♪
♪ We got the weenies ♪
♪ Sharie's
his weenie wife ♪
♪ She adds
the spices right ♪
♪ Hillbilly Hot Dog
day or night ♪
Yeeeee-haw!
[ Guy laughs ]