You know, people are
asking me all the time.
"Hey, Guy. That one joint
you checked out that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out it was
only the beginning,
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up.
And we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
Holy moly!
If you can smother it,
we'll cover it.
A chunk of buttah.
A Mexican spot
in Salt Lake City
making a million
different moles.
Any minute,
this is going in.
My sunglasses.
in Reno, Nevada...
This is for you.
...a corner joint
taking a gamble.
I got a rabbit stew,
table 2.
[Indistinct]
...with their
out-of-the-box rats.
It's about as tender
as anything that I've ever had.
And a diner
living up to their name...
-Now, Grampa's your last name?
-Yes, sir.
...with down-home
comfort cooking.
Biscuits and gravy
for you.
Send me home,
and call me Buford.
That is money.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is
"Triple d Nation."
Back in 2008,
I went to this
family-run Mexican joint
serving seven kinds
of mole
with, like, 17,000
different ingredients.
Holy moly!
And these days, they're doubling
down at their second location.
SERVER:
Here you go, guys.
This is Red Iguana.
MAN:
I love watching "Triple D."
When they did
Red Iguana,
that one was near
and dear to me.
One of those places you can't go
wrong with anything on the menu.
There's a huge menu.
There's so much variety on it.
WOMAN: Like, you want a real
authentic experience,
this is the place to come.
FIERI: That's because
Lucy Cardenas
and her husband, Bill,
are dishing out
the same family recipes
her parents did
when they opened the place
in 1985.
Okay ready.
So, "Triple D"
was maybe two years old.
2008, we cruise into
Salt Lake City, Utah.
Never been there
in my life.
And, all of a sudden,
I'm going to the house of mole.
CARDENAS: "Mole" means
"sauce," "concoction."
It's an Indian word.
I've never been to a Mexican
restaurant that had seven moles.
No.
That's your mole --
the king of mole.
So, show me what
we're gonna do.
We're gonna add tortillas
to the heated oil.
It's a natural
thickener.
And put those onions in.
Poblanos. Jalapeños.
In the pool?
In the pool.
Tomatoes.
It just keeps going.
Epazote. It's an herb.
It's licorice-y.
Parsley, cilantro,
raisins.
Boy, I haven't sous-chefed
on the mole train in a while.
A little fresh garlic.
A little.
The plantain.
Coriander.
The allspice.
Cinnamon sticks.
Here go the cloves.
Peppercorn,
marjoram.
Cumin.
The anise.
Look at that.
The only thing we didn't
put in the mole that day,
when I made mole with her,
was my sock.
[ Laughs ]
This is the thyme.
CARDENAS:
Laurel leaves.
Avocado leaves.
Yes.
That's it.
We have just gone
into a boundary
that I have not
cooked in.
Salt.
Black tar, baby.
What is the charcoal
chocolate chunky thing
that we put in the mole?
What is that called?
The beloved chimole.
The chimole.
It's a seasoning paste
we add only to mole.
So, if you
don't have this,
you've got a big hole
in your mole.
Okay.
Tastes like a flavored
charcoal briquette.
Oh, it's good.
Want me
to stir this?
Sure.
That's not charcoal.
That is chimole.
Should we just go ahead,
and put these in?
I am doing it.
Want me to help you?
Now I lost count.
Oh.
The chocolate's
going in.
And you're almost there.
We let it simmer.
Any minute.
This is going in.
My sunglasses.
Now, we have the pasilla
peppers.
chili mulatos.
So about a cup
of chicken base.
Here comes the water.
Let this all look down.
Yep.
It's gonna simmer for,
what, about an hour?
Eh, half hour.
Half hour. And then, we're gonna
get out the big mixture.
Yes, we are.
The Burr mixer.
The brr mixer.
[ Laughs ]
Brrr brr brr mixer.
So, we're gonna puree it down
to bigger chunks,
transfer it
into a blender.
Get all that done.
Okay. So, we got oil.
Then, we pour the mixture.
The blended mole.
The blended mole. Okay.
-A little salt.
-Now, we taste it?
You get a tortilla,
some delicious pinto beans.
You take your mole.
You cover it.
That's some
fantastic mole.
That's really cool of you
to share that.
It's a heck of
a family recipe.
Oh, my gosh.
It was outstanding.
Did you try the
mole amarillo?
I don't even know
what you just said.
We're gonna make
mole amarillo.
"Amarillo" means "yellow."
That's because the vegetables
are all yellow.
Yellow squash,
yellow bell peppers,
yellow chilies,
tomatoes, onions.
And then I'm going
to add epazote,
parsley, cilantro, garlic.
This is going to cook
for about 20 minutes.
So now we're going to add
our thyme and cumin, oregano,
laurel leaves, cinnamon, cloves,
marjoram, saffron.
We blend it
until it's nice and smooth.
We serve the mole with
our succulent carnitas.
One of our more popular dishes
here at Red Iguana.
Boston butts here,
granulated onion,
granulated garlic, kosher salt,
and a sachet of peppercorns
and laurel leaves.
Oranges, and we're going to
add water and boil this
for approximately a half-hour.
Now we're going to transfer
our pork into our hot oil.
We're going to add
some evaporated milk
and Mexican beer.
Now we're just going to let
this fry for 20 minutes,
and then we'll be
ready to start.
So a little oil.
I have my carnitas.
I'm going to take my mole.
Bring the carnitas to the plate.
Plantain.
A little parsley.
Mole amarillo
with carnitas.
Oh, it's amazing.
Carnitas has a really nice
crispness on the ends,
tender inside,
and then the mole
has a real good kick
to leave you with at the end.
It's not just hot sauce.
It's a richness of flavor
that I think makes carnitas
just taste so much better.
People call me all the time,
they'll just say,
"Hey, I'm going to
Salt Lake City.
We're going to go skiing.
Where do I go?
And I said if you have a day,
because it takes that long
to get in now, you've got to
go to the Red Iguana.
FIERI: Coming up, they made it
easier to get in the door...
We opened
two more restaurants.
...but choosing what to order...
Still making 18,000
different moles?
We have close to 10.
FIERI: Now that's
a whole different story.
They're all molelicious.
FIERI:
I'm back at Salt Lake City
at a joint I first stopped
by in 2008.
You know, I love Mexican food,
but especially places
that are doing it right.
I like this joint here in
Salt Lake City, The Red Iguana.
And their claim to fame
was making up some killer mole.
Seven wonders moles
of the world.
Yes, they are.
Yes, you want me
to just try 'em?
And then I'm gonna see if
I can tell you what they are.
♪♪
Okay, well, let's start off
with, "I don't know."
Okay.
This is the...
Is that ancho?
Guajillo.
Ohh.
[ Laughs ]
Is that almonds?
Almonds.
Cleanse my palate
between tastings.
This is like a fine wine.
♪♪
Okay, that's --
that's gonna be peanut.
Yeah.
There's cacahuate
in there, right?
Cacahuates.
[ Chuckles ]
They're all molelicious.
You had such a great following
before I ever got there.
How's business been?
Fantastic.
Did it expand?
We opened
two more restaurants.
-So there's three now?
-Yeah.
-Yes.
-And the second one
is two blocks
from the first one.
-It's nuts.
-And so is their new mole.
We have pistachio mole now,
which I think is delicious.
Pistachio mole.
That's a game winner.
I'm going to add my oil
to my pot
and I'm going to start
with chilies poblanos,
onion, fresh tomatoes, garlic,
chili jalapeño, epazote,
parsley, cilantro.
Stir this. We're going to add
our white wine.
Peppercorns, avocado leaf.
Okay, now we are going
to add pistachio.
Water, vegetable stock.
Let this cook for about
a half-hour,
and then we'll blend it up
and we're good to go.
We'll put some mole
on the dish.
We'll get our chicken breast.
Nice and golden.
I'm going to add
just a little bit right on top.
We sprinkle our pistachios.
Mole de pistachio.
♪♪
It's really fabulous.
I like the pistachio taste.
And there is kind of
a nutty crunch
in the mole also that I like.
It's such a rich flavor.
You can taste the pistachio.
But you can also taste
so many other infusions
of flavor in there.
You set such a great example
for me as a chef
and for the host of the show
as to what I wanted to see
from mom and pop,
multigenerational restaurants.
We'll make mole all day.
[ Laughs ]
Anytime you need me to
come back and help cook,
you let me know.
I'd love to.
Whenever you want.
Absolutely.
Especially if I lose
too much weight
and I want to put on
20 or 30 pounds.
Don't go to the belly.
There will only be
one Red Iguana
and 85,000
different moles.
[ Laughter ]
Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up in Fort Lauderdale...
The party's getting started,
man.
And you're not here!
...a diner doing the classics...
Fire the hole.
...any time of day.
Breakfast, lunch, dinner.
So legit.
That is on point, man.
-I've got biscuits, gravy.
-Mmm!
FIERI: Back in 2008,
I stopped at this
62-year-old joint
in Fort Lauderdale.
Now, it started as a bakery.
The comfort food is righteous.
I got a whole biscuit
and gravy.
FIERI: And these days, they're
still keeping it old school.
This is Grampa's Bakery
and Restaurant.
♪♪
WOMAN: Grampa's has been here
it seems like forever,
and it's really a testament
to how good they are.
It's consistently good. Kind of
reminds me of home cooking.
Like grandma used to make,
or maybe grandpa.
Ronnie Grampa.
Now Grampa is your last name?
Yes, sir.
Your dad's dad.
Did you call him Grandpa Grampa?
[ Chuckles ]
That's a good one.
[ Laughter ]
-Today is his birthday.
-Today's your birthday?
Ronnie Grampa.
Happy birthday, man.
Yeah, thanks.
[ Part horn blows ]
In 1985, Ronnie turned
the family bakery
into a full fledged diner
with the help from
general manager Tommy Grimes
and his recipes.
You're the pancake master.
I mean, a lot of people
think pancakes is just
taking the bag, tear it open,
add water, add milk.
No, we're going to
add eggs.
You're adding
the whole farm.
All kinds of stuff.
Pastry flour.
24 ounces of sugar.
FIERI: Oh, full steam
ahead, Captain!
Aye!
I learned that on the ship.
We're going to add buttermilk.
48 eggs.
One quart of fresh milk.
Let's go third speed.
Fire in the hole!
Baking powder.
Baking soda.
Two ounces of salt.
Um, I think I just
broke it.
♪♪
Uh-oh.
I had Guy run the controls.
He was cutting it up.
-Go around one more time.
-On two or three?
Three this time.
Oops. Four.
Oh! No!
The party's getting started,
man, and you're not here!
[ Laughs ]
That's a pretty elaborate
pancake mix.
Better be good.
It's gonna be. Don't worry.
I'm not.
And nothing down on there.
Nothing down.
It's got butter in it.
You never pat him.
No, you don't mess with them.
-Right.
-Oh, I'm sorry, Mary Lou Retton.
♪♪
Some people like
a chunk of butter.
A chunk of buttah!
Mmm. Look at that.
Nice layers, no holes.
It's really light,
but texturey.
Good pancake.
Today we're at Grampa's.
When that thing aired,
you know, I mean,
oh, my gosh.
It was crazy here.
I used to make pancake mix
every other day.
Now we make four times the mix
every day.
I saw Guy on "Triple D" try the
pancakes, and I said I have to
go and try the pancakes.
And now I'm hooked.
They're very fluffy
and delicious.
And the biscuits
are really good, too.
The biscuit and gravy
is absolutely fabulous.
♪♪
The recipe for
the buttermilk biscuit
is an old one for our family.
We use high-gluten flour,
cake flour,
all-purpose shortening,
baking powder, sugar,
buttermilk,
Last but not least
a little bit of salt.
And then we'll scale it out,
cut it out,
set 'em up on pans
and bake them off.
Going to make the gravy.
We start with ground
breakfast sausage,
butter, flour, salt, pepper,
and a little bit of thyme.
The last thing we add
is the milk,
and it's going to
tighten itself up.
We're going to serve it with
our fresh buttermilk biscuits.
♪♪
Here is your biscuits
and gravy.
The biscuits are light
and fluffy.
I like the gravy.
Kinda got a little tang to it.
The spice is just perfect.
It is so delicious.
MAN: This is a comfort food
kind of place.
I usually come for breakfast,
sometimes lunch.
One thing in this business,
we've got to diversify.
Kind of has a diner feel,
a pretty broad menu.
I've got a lamb shank
and a stuffed flounder.
Breakfast, lunch, dinner.
I happened to come in today
from short ribs.
It was cooked to perfection.
Basically the same process
that I did when I was
with Guy last time
when we made the lamb shanks.
We add a little salt, little
pepper to high-gluten flour.
-Dust 'em and fry 'em?
-Right.
Onions, carrots, garlic.
Add my stock.
I'm going to lift that up
and pour it right on there.
The rosemary.
This goes in the big oven now
for about two hours
and 20 minutes,
and then they'll be
ready to go.
-I've got a short rib.
-Short ribs for you.
-Thank you.
-Oh, these ribs are excellent.
It's very tender. Fall apart.
Big portions.
I wasn't expecting
this much food. [Chuckles]
The meat definitely falls
right off the bone.
The gravy is just right.
Oh, man, it's got it going on.
[ Chuckles ]
The short ribs.
Not on our regular menu.
It's a special item
like the lamb shank was.
Yeah, it just falls
right off the bone.
Send me home
and call me Buford.
That is money!
The lamb shank is now a regular
menu item because of Guy.
So legit.
That is on point, man.
The short ribs could be
a regular item on the menu, too.
♪♪
You saw good talent
when you noticed him?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Ronnie passed away
six years ago,
and that was hard,
real hard for all of us.
I think that the atmosphere
that that Ronnie created
is being carried on
by those that still work here.
As long as we can keep it going,
we're gonna keep it going.
When people learn that this is
going on in their own backyard,
they're gonna be here.
I'm telling you.
I dig it.
And everybody sure
loves this joint.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
FIERI: Coming up,
a restaurant in Reno...
You know, I don't like
a bland gland.
...serving up sweetbreads
in style.
Mmm. I'm down with it.
Saucing the Louis fries.
And I got two sweetbreads
for the bar. Let's go.
♪♪
FIERI: So here I am.
Reno, Nevada, the biggest
little city in the world,
where in 2010, I found
this joint whipping up
traditional Basque dishes
from the old country.
I've been waiting
to do this all day. Mm.
And they're still
breaking boundaries
with their unique ingredients.
This is Louis' Basque Corner.
Chicken basquaise.
I was here 10 years ago
when you guys
did your original show.
-You guys want some?
-Yeah.
Pass it on down.
I can only say it got better.
It's a fun atmosphere
and it's really good food.
Two beef tongue.
Table two.
I am full Basque.
We eat with gusto.
We love our food.
We love our conversation.
And that's what Louis does.
FIERI:
That's 'cause Louis Erreguible
was from the Basque region.
He came to the US
to be a sheep herder,
but took a left turn and opened
this place in 1967 instead.
This place was packed.
Lined up all over the place.
What do you mean,
this place was packed?
This place is packed now.
[ Laughter ]
It's not French food.
It's not Spanish food.
It's got its own twist.
It's Basque.
We tried to keep the tradition
of it, that flavor.
I love it.
WOMAN: Guy really put a focus on
not just the food,
but the culture and the people
that make
this place a restaurant.
I mean, you got Frank
in the kitchen
doing a great job.
Oh, I love Frank.
FIERI: That would be
Chef Frank Vargus.
Traditional Basque food
is more like a comfort food,
something that takes
a long time to cook.
What sheepherder's
used to make,
oxtail bourguignon, beef tongue,
rabbit,
sweetbreads.
The thymus gland?
Yes, sir.
[ Bleating ]
It's a traditional Basque dish.
I feel that I have got
a fiduciary responsibility
to once in a while,
just break out
and try something
that I know I don't like
just so you all can
play it on your DVR
and rewind it
and play it again --
And play it again.
[ Slow-motion ]
Thank you.
Going to throw
them all in there.
That's a big bucket
of thymus gland, friend.
[ Sighs ]
Add some water.
We're going to season
this water at all?
We are going to put some
rock salt.
Because, you know,
I don't like a bland gland.
[ Laughs ] And we're
going to let her boil.
A little ice in there
and let the fat kind of come up.
And now we're going bobbing
for sweetbreads.
Look at those morsels.
We're gonna let them
cool down completely.
Chunk them up into
nice little chunks.
Chunk 'em up.
That's all for you.
[ Chuckles ]
Get our pan nice and hot,
and put some olive oil
in it.
Our sweetbreads in.
Then I'm gonna add
the garlic.
Garlic helps everything.
peppers, onions and some
nice sliced mushrooms.
Garlic, salt, and pepper,
and then we're going to
flambé it with sweet vermouth.
And the sweet vermouth
really gives them
a nice different twinge.
Did you say "twinge"?
Yeah.
Made up your own word?
♪♪
Well, fans of "Triple D,"
once again, I embark
on a unique food item.
I've had lamb's tongue,
calf fries,
turtle, pig ear, pig tail.
And now the thymus gland.
He said it was his third time
trying sweetbreads.
This is for you.
And that the first two times,
he said he spit 'em out
'cause he really
didn't care for 'em.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Just kidding.
It's about as tender as
anything that I've ever had.
It takes on the flavor
incredibly well.
If you're going to try 'em, this
is the way to get after 'em.
How else have you
had them?
We cook them in a wine sauce
and add them to our fries.
I'm down with it.
Everybody's favorite.
We decided to name them
after Louis himself.
We're going to start off
by melting some butter.
We're going to add to that
pureed bell peppers, onions,
mushrooms, garlic.
And we're going to reduce
some red wine.
Sweet vermouth,
add it to our sauce.
Now I'm gonna add a little red
pepper and a little parsley,
a little bit of beef broth.
As soon as it comes to a boil,
we'll add our roux.
After our sweet breads
are browned,
we're going to add sauce
to our pan.
Mushrooms, and add those
sweetbreads,
and let him cook off
a little bit.
♪♪
Now we're going to finish off
our fries.
Put a little salt, garlic,
and mix it up real good.
We plate it and put
the sweetbreads
and that wine sauce on top.
Put a little goat cheese,
just a touch of parsley.
Taking Louis fries
to table two.
They're so tender and so
luscious. Just wonderful.
Sweetbreads are maybe
like a delicacy.
Then you put them
over some potatoes,
I mean, it's a filler upper.
It's delicious.
This is a great dish,
plus a great restaurant,
plus a great environment.
It has a feeling of home. A lot
of Basque tradition in here.
Louie, unfortunately,
passed away a couple years ago.
And before he passed away,
he taught me everything he knew
about the Basque dishes
that he knew.
He instilled in me
to keep his tradition going
in this restaurant.
FIERI: Which is happening
with new owner Chris Shanks.
VARGUS: When he bought
this restaurant from Louis,
he agreed to keep the recipes
and the staff.
So that's why tradition goes
on here at Louis' Basque Corner.
People enjoy their food and
their recipe and their taste.
Just to see how Chris
has really kept that alive,
Louis would be proud.
FIERI: You come in as strangers,
you leave as family.
That's exactly what
I want to do.
Get down here.
Get down here now.
♪♪
You guys enjoy.
FIERI: But these joints aren't
the only ones taking tastebuds
on a test drive.
Now for our main event.
That's two short ribs all day.
Mole amarillo with succulent
carnitas up, please.
We'll keep adding to the menu
when we visit more places
right here on "Triple D Nation."
Get in and grab
one of those for you.
So in the Basque --
Whoa!
Yeah, nuggety.
It's got its own little bit
of nodules and nuggulals.
-Yes, it does.
-[ Whistles ]