You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That one joint you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple-D'?
How they doing?"
You know? I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple-D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
It's a burger...
Bacon is money.
...and barbecue...
You got to go under,
under, baby, go under.
...bonanza.
Mr. Whitner's
barbecue sauce.
An OG Oklahoma City spot
racking up ridiculous ribs...
You good at describing.
Go ahead and do your thing.
This ain't my show
right now.
...out-of-bounds brisket and
burnt ends in Virginia Beach.
Hey, look,
what's that over there?
[ Laughs ]
And in Roy, Utah...
That's great.
...burgers passed down
through the generations.
What a story.
I can read the book.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So over 12 years ago,
in the first season
of "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
we were here in Oklahoma City
to check out a joint
that was known for their ribs
and their barbecue sauce.
It's time for a revisit.
This is Leo's Barbecue Factory.
I've got two wraps up.
Get them while they hot.
Ooh, roasting, baby.
"Triple-D" really knocked it
out of the park.
Great, great barbecue.
It's a landmark
in Oklahoma City.
FIERI: Since 1974 when Leo Smith
founded this place.
And when he passed away
20 years later,
his son Charles stepped onstage.
Welcome to Oklahoma City.
FIERI: I like it, man.
This is our house.
It's your house
while you're here.
♪♪
FIERI: Where's trouble?
Hey, Sonny.
I didn't come all this way
for this.
My hair turned gray,
it took you so long
to come this way.
Welcome back
to Oklahoma City.
If you don't remember
from that first season
of "Triple-D"
just how whacked-out
this cat was...
I'm fast and I'm pretty.
I'm not kidding you.
There was one liner
after one liner after one liner.
The fill-in folks used
to be out there,
but now they're inside.
The fill --
Yeah, we filling you up
in here, baby.
Wait a minute, Guy.
What's that you smell?
Do you smell it?
♪ Love is in the air ♪
They say the proof
is in the pudding,
but it's also
in the taste.
I'mma put it
in front of your face.
I feel like
I'm talking to Ali.
No, you're talking
to Charlie.
You know, you have not
slowed down at all.
I've talked to people --
Where are you?
Let me take this --
Can I --
Yeah, go ahead
and take it off.
Getting hot in here.
It was funny until
it started getting hot in here.
Good to see you, Guy.
You too, brother.
So give me the rundown.
You're still doing
the St. Louis ribs.
SMITH: Yeah. We putting it down
still the same way.
So what is the seasoning
that you made?
SMITH: All we're simply using
is black pepper and salt.
Putting these
little piggies on.
-What do you smoke with?
-Hickory.
Just hickory.
Hickory.
So these are
ready to rock?
No sauce recommended?
SMITH: That's without.
That's really good.
Please remember,
red is hot
and the brown is not.
One is bound
to hit the spot.
Ketchup, vinegar, whole
lot of love.
Watch your finger, baby.
Mmm. Mmm.
I could very easily
take a shot of this in my mouth.
Now we'll go hot.
Okay.
[ Strained ]
I can handle this.
FIERI:
You change any recipes?
We're doing spare ribs
and St. Louis ribs
because some people
like the rib tip.
The difference between
the spare rib and the St. Louis,
you can get the rib tip
right off the top.
Ohh!
I'm just joking.
I've seen that same joke.
He's done it a million times.
It's still funny.
Let me check.
All your fingers still there?
Uh, no.
How's it taste?
[ Mouth full ]
Delicious.
Still running
the same two pits?
Same two.
They getting old.
I was gonna say,
they falling apart yet?
Yeah, they look like it.
Dad always said
if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
Am I just getting a lot
of the smoke in my face?
Check out one of them
fire safety classes.
You got to go under,
under, baby, go under the smoke.
You know,
I'm a little rusty.
Don't you go flipping
that knife.
People will say, "Did you see
that guy flip that?"
Yeah. My dad used to send me
home for doing that.
Yeah? Okay.
What are you gonna make me?
I got into the wrap game.
Now I'm a certified
wrapper.
Okay.
We simply put
the tortilla down.
Then we put a little
of this cheese on it.
We gonna put some
of this brisket on it
because I know you
want some brisket.
How long was that on?
SMITH: About 20 hours.
Look at that.
Got some fried taters
right here.
Shake off the haters
with the taters.
Butter, 'tatos,
more butter, onions.
More butter, mushrooms,
all-purpose seasoning
and some jalapeños
like so.
Leo's sour cream sauce --
three parts sour cream,
one part Leo's sauce.
Okay.
We put a little
on top like so.
Alright.
Then we get the mushrooms.
What three people
are coming to eat this?
Just you and me, baby.
That's you.
Jalapeños.
This is like
the kitchen sink.
You like a little lime
one time.
Oh! Voilà!
Then we do it like that,
get a little paper
to catch the vapor.
Uh-huh. Show you right.
Okay.
Is this on the menu
or is it just --
[ Grunts ]
Did you just grunt?
I said, "Uhh!"
That's a verbal
exclamation mark.
♪♪
Dynamite.
I'll call it a taco.
Dynamite brisket taco.
Got that little crunch.
You describe it.
You good at describing.
Go ahead and do your thing.
This ain't my show
right now.
This is all about you,
brother.
Make it happen, captain.
That's pure happiness,
that's joy.
SERVER: Beef wrap for you.
I really like how the onions
married with the brisket.
It almost tastes caramelized.
I also really love the sauce.
There's a little bit
of sweetness,
smokiness from the brisket,
but it also has, like,
a breakfast taco feel.
It is still the same
fantastic interior
of a smoky gas station
I remember it to be.
You know, the main thing is
the light bulbs don't match.
Well, when you
get your plate,
the last thing
you gonna look at...
FIERI: Coming up,
there's plenty more to see.
Can you taste the love?
Unh.
An oldie but a goodie...
Cake is free
with every dinner.
Make you feel
like a winner.
Keep eating that
and you won't be any thinner.
Uh-huh.
...and the new kid on the block.
It's the real deal,
brother.
FIERI:
I'm back in Oklahoma City
checking out what this OG
"Triple-D" joint's been up to
since I was there in 2007.
I'm glad to see
that the barbecue
and the boss are still the same.
[ Laughing ]
Only at Leo's, baby.
Unh.
This right here, I mean,
that's gourmet, baby.
Unh.
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
[ Laughs ]
When you get your plate
and your eyes get heavy,
you're gonna be heavy
like a '57 Chevy.
[ Horn honks ]
FIERI: There's certain
"Triple-D" joints --
All of those in that
first season that we had --
showed everybody
what we were looking for,
what we were gonna do.
And we had never met
anybody like you.
You stand
in your own lane.
How busy has it been?
It's been crazy busy
after you left.
I had a line that I just
could not handle.
Dude, you're crushing it.
I talk to people
all the time that come here.
Matter of fact, my manager is
here with me and he goes,
"Man, I just had
that strawberry cake.
You ain't lying."
♪♪
I can go anywhere.
I can go in the state capital
without my logo
or anything on.
If they can see that
strawberry banana cake,
they'll say, "Leo's."
Now, what is the icing
made of?
It's made of some...
Don't say "love."
Of course.
Love is in everything.
We coat it like that.
We pull it straight
out of the oven, so it's warm.
So it's absorbing this
as you put it on.
Okay.
We put our bananas
in the middle layer.
Unh, like that.
Okay.
Then we gonna put
our icing on the top.
We put free slices
of this with every dinner
up here at Leo's.
No.
Yeah.
Cake is free
with every dinner.
Make you feel
like a winner.
Keep eating that and you
won't be any thinner.
Unh.
Slice some banana.
We gonna put it on top.
Now we're going with
the strawberries.
Just like that.
Then we get a little bit
of this enticing icing.
We drizzle it
over the top like so.
It doesn't set, rest,
take a moment, have a --
I mean, there's nothing
you say to it?
Just thank you, baby,
for being so lovely to me.
Now is everybody's cake
still a little bit warm?
Most of the time
when they come right at 11:00,
that's when the cakes
come out of the oven.
I mean, it's great.
It tastes like a big, gigantic
strawberry shortcake.
How many of those
you go through a week now?
About 100, 120.
A week?
It's the real deal.
Is the chicken
the bomb?
-The best.
-The chicken's great.
That's a good hot link.
Wow.
That's a hot hot link.
Have you ever tried
the vegetarian platter here?
-No.
-No. What is that?
[ Laughs ]
Now we have
a cucumber salad --
cucumbers,
tomatoes and onions,
vinegar, canola oil
and seasonings.
It's complimentary when you come
in to dine at Leo's.
We also sell it to go.
Cucumber salad.
The salad is
a great little starter
before you get your entrée.
MAN:
It's good. It's light.
And then you get your entrée,
then you get your cake.
It just makes
the whole experience great.
I had a fever
for the flavor.
You're a poet.
Oh, I didn't know it.
Give me a little "Triple-D
Nation" rhyme out.
Lord knows I'm glad
you chose to come to Leo's.
Next time you're in OKC,
come to 36th and Kelley,
fill up your belly.
Oklahoma City's
finest since '74.
Let the world know.
Like that.
Get some.
FIERI: Coming up...
Everything's low fat.
Everything.
...an old-school hamburger
stand in Roy, Utah...
Started with you.
Second generation,
third generation.
...grilling up
good old-fashioned burgers...
Man, that's good.
...and some surprises
between the bun.
Like real buffalo?
I've got your goat burger.
FIERI: Back in 2008, I went
to this joint in Roy, Utah.
Now, Salt Lake City is,
like, 35 miles that way.
15 miles that way,
some killer skiing.
But for a lot of people,
this is the destination.
A little burger joint that's
been doing it right
for over 52 years.
Now the third generation's
taking over
and the fourth's not far behind.
This is Burger Bar.
♪♪
I found out about Burger Bar
through "Triple-D."
I came over.
Loved it ever since.
WOMAN:
They have a large menu.
A lot of different items.
Never been disappointed.
MAN #2: I love this place.
It's kind of like a family vibe
when you come and get burgers.
FIERI: That's because it's run
by a family -- the Fowlers.
And it all began
back when Ben and Rita
opened in 1956.
♪♪
Started with you.
Second generation,
third generation.
Everybody's worked here?
-Everybody. We had to.
When "Triple-D" came,
my dad was actually phasing out
and I was wanting
to take over.
Of the siblings
that work here,
you're kind of...
I'm a top dog.
You're top dog.
That's right.
Jessica did
a really good job.
FIERI: Now she's sharing the
limelight with her brother Joe.
JESSICA: We're kind of fighting
over who's top dog.
I think it's me.
I let her think it's her.
♪♪
Now,
how can you look so good
working on a burger line?
Oh, everything's low fat.
Everything.
[ Giggles ]
Guy had one of
our Big Ben Burgers.
The Ben is our
specialty hamburger.
It's named
after my grandfather.
What is it?
This is our round,
sliced bacon.
Round, sliced bacon?
Yeah.
Where's the meat
come from?
They grind the meat daily.
So it's never frozen.
No. And we like
to put our cheese on
so it's melted,
and we toast our bun.
Alright.
Come over here.
You want to add
the fry sauce?
Salad dressing
and ketchup.
Whoa!
The first burger I made,
I actually put
too much sauce on it.
At least you don't
hold back on that.
♪♪
That's great.
The burger's really juicy.
The bacon is money,
and then the fry sauce...
Do you like the fry sauce?
I mean, it's salad dressing.
and ketchup. Come on.
You'll have to try
the steak one. Really.
Really? Is it good?
Really.
JOE: Here's your steak
tenderloin Ben with drinks.
These are our 3-ounce
steak tenderloins.
So I'm gonna throw that
on the grill
and get a good sear on it.
We're gonna dress this up
with just a little bit of mayo,
lettuce, pickle
and some butter on the bun.
There she goes.
JOE: Here you know, guys, I got
your steak tenderloin Bens.
It is the best steak.
I have never had one
that was not tender.
Just really a good sandwich.
MAN #3: I love the steak Ben.
The meat is fresh and local,
but every once in a while,
it's nice to have an exotic
burger and exotic meat.
JESSICA: When Guy was here,
he tried the buffalo
and the elk burger.
Like real buffalo?
Yeah.
It's got great texture.
It's good.
You like buffalo burgers?
Yeah, I really do.
Let's try the elk.
Okay.
Man, that's good.
You like it?
Mmm. Excellent.
We also do an exotic meat
of the month.
So it's a rotating meat.
There's just so many
different types of meats.
It's amazing. I've seen
swordfish, camel, goat.
Now we're gonna
start our goat burger.
Gonna put some sautéed onions
with butter on those.
So here's our goat patty.
It's a third of a pound.
We just cook these through.
I'm just gonna
press it out a little bit
and then I'll put a lid on it
to keep some of the moisture in.
We have this thicker
cut of mozzarella
and the onions.
Get it melted.
Now it's done.
We're gonna put this on our bun
and put the dressing on it.
Joe actually came up
with this sauce.
It's our balsamic pesto aioli.
Little bit of mayo, pesto,
balsamic vinegar,
and some cumin.
The cumin just adds
that extra kick
and kind of
like a balance of flavors.
Our garden tomatoes.
We like lot of tomato.
And there's
our exotic goat burger.
It's the meat of the month.
it's a very lean, gamey meat.
I like that personally.
No other restaurant
has anything like that.
Somehow goat and cheese
go together.
It's kind of a culinary fit.
♪♪
So it's actually so crazy
how busy it got.
They tell us to expect
like a 30% jump.
And it was definitely that
and then some.
you can't get a burger that
tastes like this anywhere else.
That's my friend.
She was featured
on the show as a customer.
And then she ended up
marrying Joe.
Now they have five kids.
I've got your goat burger.
Thank you.
Never dreamed it would be
this big and forever.
I didn't know it would go on
for generations.
FIERI: This is unique,
culinarily diverse.
I mean, you name it,
you've got a piece of it
going on here.
JESSICA: It's nice to be
a part of something
that my grandpa started
and that my dad took over.
And we're third generation now,
and hopefully his kids will
maybe even take over.
I got to tell you,
what a story.
I can read the book.
What a novel.
FIERI: Coming up
in Virginia Beach...
Genuine.
...another family-run
restaurant.
Nice rub.
...doing some
serious smoking...
Good smoke.
...and saucing.
-Got to get that tang.
-Wu-Tang.
FIERI: Back in 2011,
I was in Virginia Beach
searching for some seafood.
When I hear this dude that's
knocking out burnt ends,
North Carolina pulled pork
and smoked turkey,
you know I got
to check it out.
And they're still
cranking out that killer 'cue.
This is Whitner's Barbecue...
♪♪
2-piece barbecue.
I think Whitner's is
the best barbecue place
in Virginia Beach.
MAN #4:
We come here quite a bit.
And we saw it on the Food
Network, and we were like,
"Hey, that's our Whitner's."
FIERI: ...run by restaurant
rookie Warren Rogers.
But he doesn't exactly
look like a newbie.
How old were you when
you chose to do this?
Uh, 52.
Yeah, that's when most people
just jump right off the end.
Just jump right off
the end of the ship
is what I say.
Yeah.
It was just very exciting.
I was mostly a wreck.
FIERI: Okay.
What are we making?
Mr. Whitner's
barbecue rub.
You want to look at that
camera, don't you?
I know it.
Just come on.
Just get on over here.
There you go.
[ Laughs ]
Mr. Whitner's
barbecue sauce.
You don't want to be
like this, you know.
Alright, Mr. Whitner's
barbecue rub.
Okay. Lot of salt.
Then we go
with the brown sugar
and some black pepper.
And that's it.
You got it.
What's that fantastic hum
I keep hearing?
Oh, it's our smoker.
It goes 24 hours a day.
Hit this
all over the brisket.
And let that seasoning work
its way down
through the meat
as we cook it.
From what temp?
200.
For how many hours? 12.
12. Yep.
Nice.
I think he was very impressed
with the way
that we smoked the brisket.
Is that working?
Genuine, good beef,
nice rub, good smoke,
rendered down.
Way to go.
MAN #4: The brisket in general
here is one of my favorites.
It's smoky, it's juicy.
It's got a nice crust.
FIERI: And they're serving it up
in style.
And the brisket is gonna go
right on top
of just a simple piece
of white bread.
And we will smother this
with our homemade gravy.
It just starts with a simple
roux of butter and flour.
Start with some salt,
chili powder,
garlic powder and onion powder.
Whisk in our chicken stock
for about 5 to 10 minutes.
And at that point,
it will be ready to smother
our brisket.
Open-faced brisket.
WOMAN #2: This is absolutely
tender, juicy.
It was wonderful.
I don't want to share
with my husband.
WOMAN #3: It's almost like
a melt in your mouth.
Never had it before.
I would eat it lot.
WOMAN #4: I usually
get the open-faced brisket.
Well, it's a toss up
between that and the burnt ends.
We are widely known
for our burnt ends.
Check this out.
So we're making all burnt ends
out of this?
WARREN: Yes.
Slice it into cubes.
You got it.
Hit it with sauce.
Okay, what sauce
are we making?
Sweet sauce.
A little white vinegar.
That'll clear you out.
Cider vinegar.
Little chili powder.
You've got it.
Pepper.
You're too tall
to be doing that job.
That's all right.
I can get on down.
Ground mustard.
Granulated garlic.
Onion powder.
Whitner's barbecue rub.
Some ground celery.
Mess of salt.
There you go.
Brown sugar.
Man.
We'll get this
all mixed in.
What's next?
Pineapple juice.
And more pineapple juice.
Yeah.
More cider vinegar?
Got to get that tang.
Wu-Tang.
There you go.
Big Wu-Tang Clan fan
over here.
That sauce is righteous.
WARREN: Alright.
Put this baby back in the oven.
And that's where the magic
happens with the burnt ends.
Just cooked it down
and it just
absorbed the sauce.
Look at that big smoke ring
on that.
That's how she goes.
♪♪
Nice job.
Thank you.
Really nice job.
I'll be back for this for sure.
Hey, look,
what's that over there?
♪♪
WARREN: After the show aired,
business just about tripled.
Half slab platter.
We did not know about Whitner's
until they were on "Triple-D"
years ago.
We came in then
and have loved it ever since.
Well, looky loo at that.
Mmm.
That is a righteous
turkey sandwich, man.
My son Chris is now in charge
of the whole restaurant.
CHRIS: You know, when Guy
comes to your restaurant,
you've got to make sure
the food stays good.
Bay of Pigs.
Warren and Chris, they're always
coming up with new recipes.
MAN #4: This is the first time
I've had the Bay of Pigs.
Definitely a new favorite.
CHRIS: Bay of Pigs
Cuban sandwich.
We're gonna be rubbing our
pork loin with the Latin rub.
We want this pork loin
to pack a punch.
We're gonna smoke this
at 200 degrees
for about 60 to 90 minutes.
Now we're gonna be
rubbing a bone-in pork butt
with our barbecue rub.
Get an even coating
all the way around.
Smoke this overnight
at 200 degrees.
Give it a quick, rough chop,
and then we'll just mix that
with our North Carolina
vinegar sauce.
We have our chipotle mayonnaise.
Lots of flavor here.
And then just have
our pickle pepper relish,
pulled pork
our smoked pork loin,
ham with melted Swiss.
Bun goes on.
So here we have our Bay
of Pigs sandwich.
MAN #5: The Bay of Pigs Cuban
sandwich is delicious.
A little bit of juice,
a little bit of tang.
You kind of get
that bite to it.
It's amazing.
I will tell you,
Warren,
you're rocking it out,
man.
Thanks for having me, man.
I need a t-shirt.
You got it.
What size you wear?
Big Ben
for the "Triple-D Nation."
FIERI: But these joints are just
the tip of the barbecue iceberg.
Got one wrap up.
Come get it while it's hot.
We'll be popping
into more places
next time on "Triple-D Nation."
And the roof caved in
and so I had to rebuild it.
You remodeled?
Yeah, I remodel--
I re-fixed the roof.
You re-fixed the roof.
I did.
I repaired the roof.
How's that?
Let's get this straight.
I don't know.