You know, folks ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy.
That one joint you checked out
in that one city when you
were doing 'Triple D',
how they doing?"
You know what? I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip --
we're cruising the East Coast...
You come into my town.
and teach me how to bulldog.
...checking in on some
favorite local meats.
In Richmond, Virginia,
a neighborhood diner serving up
the same dynamite dishes...
Can't you hear it singing?!
...but dialing it up
with a second spot.
So, you just have fair game
to do whatever you want.
A mother-son duo in Boston
still make it chilaquiles...
This is a body
by chilaquiles.
...and chile rellenos their way.
Damn, that's good.
[ Chuckles ]
Plus, this Baltimore beef stand
is so outrageous...
That will just clean you
right out, won't it?
...I'm hitting it up
for a three-peat.
FIERI: Number-one seller.
-"Triple D."
-Yes! See?
Mm-hmm.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Alright. So, I'm here,
in Richmond, Virginia.
And now back in 2007,
we shot this place,
and if I remember
things correctly,
I pulled right up here
with my car.
Jimmy, what happened?
We got bigger.
We built.
Oh, by the way,
this is Dot's Back Inn.
♪♪
Falafel gyro!
I saw Dot's on "Triple D,"
and the food looked amazing.
I was on the first episode...
I've been coming here
for about 17 years
...and now it is 29 years.
Guy came in,
and I was sitting right there.
FIERI: Chicken MacArthur.
MacArthur Avenue.
My pictures back there
on the wall.
So, I got proof I was here.
FIERI: I do, too.
It was the first time I met
owner Jimmy Tsamouras.
♪♪
Do you prefer to
go by Jimmy, Jim Boy,
Jimmy Crack Corn?
Jimmy, don't hit me
with that spatula.
[ Both laugh ]
That's my favorite one.
I like that one.
You look good, man.
Thank you, man,
I feel good.
You're missing the sunglasses
on the hat.
I took them off.
You just bought Dot's Back Inn
when I first met you, Right?
Yeah.
From previous owner
Cookie Giannini.
So, you had the restaurant
for how long?
16 years.
I start coming by more
and more often, wooing here.
It happened
very quickly.
And I promised here
I was going to change it.
He said if it's not broke,
you don't fix it.
Pretty much, everything
that's still on the menu
were items that were on the menu
when I had it.
You still serving the MacArthur?
Still doing the MacArthur,
absolutely,
I remember it.
TSAMOURAS: Fair amount
of olive oil,
'cause that's basically
our sauce.
Whoa!
Look at that, man!
I cut those onions so thin,
they only got one side.
[ Sighs ]
So, you put
the protein in now,
slows down
the cooking process.
That is correct.
Doesn't let that garlic burn.
You want to stir
that up a little bit?
I don't know.
I'm not a stirrer.
I'm a tosser.
Alright.
Well, toss it.
Okay.
How about some
artichoke hearts.
Okay!
A little bit
of wine in there.
Spaghetti.
-Feta cheese, man.
-Oh, look at that.
Look at that sauce
that's coming up right there.
That's money, baby.
[ Chuckling ] Yeah!
Down for about
five minutes.
Yeah.
Melt the feta,
heat up the pasta a little bit.
We'll put it on our plate.
♪♪
You want to know what I think,
don't you?
It's like talking
in the middle of an opera.
Can't you
hear it singing?!
[ Operatic singing ]
That's good, man.
TSAMOURAS: Chicken McArthur's
is still on the menu,
and it is one of the most
popular dishes that we have.
Until this airs,
and then it will be
the Dot's Chicken Smithfield.
We are going to put our onions
and our Smithfield ham in.
Caramelize our onions
a little bit.
Bringing out
our chicken breasts.
A little bit of salt and pepper,
not too much.
Mushrooms.
We're gonna flame
with brandy.
Here we go.
♪♪
Then we're going to add
our heavy cream,
and when the chicken is ready,
we will pour it over warm rice
and a little fresh parsley.
Chicken Smithfield, pick up!
♪♪
The chicken is cooked
to perfection.
MAN: I enjoy the sauce,
and anything that's got
ham or bacon on it,
you gotta be sold.
The hardest part about Dot's
is knowing what to get.
I've only got a menu?
Can I get a Lunch Pail menu,
please?
Can I get a Brunch menu,
It's gonna
take me all month.
What was a pancake called?
The Black Bean Corn Cakes.
Take your regular
pancake batter.
Regular buttermilk
So the corn is in the cake?
The corn is in the cake.
Sprinkle it around.
Okay.
Nice hot black beans.
Provolone cheese.
Let's see.
Oh, yeah.
There you go.
Put a little
tomatoes on top.
Salsa and sour cream.
♪♪
That's good.
Those beans are
really tasty.
The sauce
is really good.
That's great.
Tiny kitchen,
big flavor.
You haven't changed.
You promise it wouldn't.
It's the same great food,
same great people.
We keep
the menu the same.
They do an amazing job.
The falafel is wonderful.
Falafel gyro!
We're gonna make a falafel gyro.
These garbanzo beans
have been soaking overnight.
We're gonna pulse them...
so they get evenly popped.
Now we're gonna add
our cilantro, parsley,
and our spices --
salt, pepper, garlic,
onion, cumin, coriander.
♪♪
Then I'm gonna add a little
soda water to moisten it up.
The carbonation --
it makes it a lot lighter
and a lot fluffier.
We want it to sit
for at least 12 hours,
and this will
become a nice paste.
We are going to scoop
our falafel balls
and fry them till
they're golden-brown.
We're gonna take
some pita bread,
tzatziki, romaine lettuce.
We will grab our falafels.
Can't have too much tzatziki.
We have our diced
tomatoes and onions.
SERVER: Pick up, falafel gyro!
I'm a sucker for a falafel.
Everything in it is
just delicious and fresh.
Tender, it was flavorful.
It was really good.
♪♪
So, how's business been?
Business has been phenomenal.
Awesome.
Business has been great.
Bought another restaurant.
This is Demi's, right?
Literally,
right down the street.
Named after your daughter.
Breakfast and lunch?
Dinner only.
[ Laughs ]
They have taken
the special board from Dot's
and elevated it to Demi's.
There is a shrimp santorini,
the pastitsio.
So, you just have fair game
to do whatever you want.
That's it.
What do you
got here, Neal?
You were in the first
of all the cookbooks.
Wow!
Look at this.
Here's me, you, my wife.
And wait a second.
Why does --
Why does Jimmy look skinnier,
and I don't?
[ Chuckles ]
If you and I hung out
on a regular basis,
besides jail,
we'd be fat.
[ Both laugh ]
I do what I do,
but the restaurant,
the chef, the owner,
you have to back up
the other side of it,
and you've definitely
done it, man.
Well, thank you.
Congrats.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up...
I don't need to be here.
... a Boston spot...
Wicked bueno!
...dippin' south of the border.
That's chili-hurry-up-a.
Chili-killing me.
♪♪
So, here I am,
on the east side of Boston,
one of my favorite places now.
Last couple of times I was here
was all Italian.
Mmm!
There is nothing
I would change on that.
But then I found
this little Mexican place,
where a mother-son team
was cooking recipes
straight from their hometown.
And these days,
that dynamic duo is
still working the line together,
here at Angelo's Cafe.
♪♪
Chilaquiles verdes.
WOMAN: It's very
authentic Mexican food.
That's why I love
coming here.
MAN: We saw
the "Triple D" episode,
and we were so excited and proud
to see Angela's featured.
Great example of Eastie pride
right there.
FIERI: And the man
behind the magic, well,
that would be Luis Garcia,
who learned everything he knows
about cooking from his mom.
My mom has been in
the restaurant business
for like 50 years.
We have the restaurant business
in our blood.
In your blood.
My ma is really strict
when it comes to cooking.
She wants to everything perfect.
Oh, okay.
What's your mom's name?
Angela.
Hence the name
of the restaurant.
That's the name
of restaurant.
My mother's still
cooking in the kitchen.
She loves to cook authentic
family recipes.
Mole poblano.
From Pueblo?
From Pueblo.
♪♪
Very nicely done.
Pipian rojo con nopales.
♪♪
This isn't
your typical Mexican dish.
If you're used to going
into a Mexican restaurant...
and getting chilaquiles,
this would be
something different.
Oh, but he's got those, too!
Have you tried
them before?
Brother,
what do you think this is?
This is a body by chilaquiles.
Alright, good.
Come on, man.
What we're gonna make
is tomatillo sauce.
Take the tomatillos
and the jalapeños
out of the hot water.
Wow!
There you go. See?
Right handed,
over back.
That's like
a tennis move.
So now we add a little water,
garlic.
♪♪
Then you got to cook the sauce
a little bit.
Exactly.
Okay.
We have to add the epazote.
I know epazote.
You can't find that very often.
We're just gonna let that
steep in there.
And then we just pour
a little salt in here.
Okay.
We put the tortilla chips.
Yep, so they're still gonna have
a little bit of crunch to them,
just a little bit
of texture.
We're gonna start
cooking the eggs.
[ Chuckling ] No!
You like eggs?
No, but I'll be back.
How do you want them?
Whatever you do,
do not let them be runny.
So, over-hard, right?
Over there
would be better.
Alright, good.
He doesn't like the eggs.
♪♪
I don't need to be here.
It's like me saying,
I don't like the beach.
[ Laughs ]
Let's have some
chilaquiles.
Hot. That's chili-hurry-up-a.
Chili-killing me.
We're gonna garnish it
with the sour cream.
Shredded chicken.
Some fresco cheese.
Some fresco.
A little bit onions.
Add a couple...
Refritos.
And the eggs.
There you go.
On the side!
Good man!
♪♪
Mmm!
The bite, the heat.
the crunch, the cream.
the chicken,
the money!
I'm coming to get
this tomorrow.
♪♪
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
Damn, that's good.
[ Laughs ]
When people saw the show
and saw the chilaquiles,
it became, like, famous.
It's an authentic
Mexican breakfast dish.
FIERI: And so is this one!
We're gonna make
a huevos rancheros
on a salsa roja.
This is my mother's recipe,
especially when when it comes
to making the sauce.
So, what we have here
is the plum tomatoes.
real chili...and garlic.
Water.
We blend the sauce
for five minutes.
Strain it.
We do this to make sure
it's not too thick.
FIERI: Oh-oh!
This is part
of the show.
I've never seen
the Bruce Lee cooking technique.
[ Chuckling ]
Exactly.
That is...
So...
I've never seen that.
This is a technique
that we use all the time.
♪♪
Add the chicken bouillon
and the epazote.
A little bit of water.
Let it boil 10 minutes.
You've got to cook
over-easy eggs.
Fried corn tortilla.
Refried beans.
The eggs are cooked,
and then we're ready
to put them on the plate.
The sauce that we made earlier,
fresh cheese, onions,
and avocado.
And it's ready to serve.
Huevos rancheros
salsa roja.
WOMAN: They're delicious.
There's really nice red sauce.
Everything's really complex,
but it fits together
really well.
I love the way
the huevos rancheros
It's always delicious.
Everything's homemade.
Otherwise, Angela gets upset.
You call her Angela.
or you call her mom?
Mom.
This is very authentic
and from the Puebla region.
I like the mole,
like the huevos rancheros
and the chiles rellenos.
SERVER: Chiles Rellenos
GARCIA: We gonna
grill the peppers.
Now we're gonna peel
our peppers.
Really, really gentle.
You stuff them
with queso fresco,
and then we start
doing the batter.
First, we're gonna
put them in a flower
and then the egg whites.
We use the whites --
makes it, like, nice and fluffy.
For a bit of flavor,
we add the egg yolk.
♪♪
We're ready to fry them.
And this is ready.
I got two chiles rellenos
for table four!
I love the light breading.
I love the cheese inside.
It's not too spicy.
It's incredible.
[ Vocalizing ]
[ Bell dinging ]
After "Triple D" came,
it was, like, insane.
The wait was like
an hour and a half.
We decide to open
a second location.
We love both restaurants.
It's been a great fit
into the neighborhood.
Awesome.
Fantastic.
Wicked bueno!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Now, coming up...
I did not ever
see that coming.
...pit beef in Baltimore...
That hand outta there.
...I just can't get enough of.
I think we should have it
every single way
you could possibly make it.
♪♪
You know,
if there's one question
you guys all ask me,
it's, "Guy,
do you have a favorite
'Triple D' joint?"
Well, it's impossible to say,
but I'll tell you this --
when I roll back into Baltimore,
there's one joint
I got gotta check out,
because since
I was there in 2008,
they popped up
all over the place.
This is the one and only
Chaps Pit Beef.
♪♪
I started going to Chaps
in 1987.
We knew Guy would love it.
Everybody else does.
MAN: A lot of people
make pit beef.
A lot of people
don't get it right,
but they get it right here.
It's always very tasty.
FIERI: Probably because owners
Bob and Donna Creager have
been working the charcoal
over 30 years.
As a wedding gift,
my father gave me
this little shack.
DONNA: He said that we should
put a pit beef stand
outside of his nightclub.
FIERI: But it wasn't the
nightlife that got me there.
It was my buddy ship,
Chef Duff Goldman.
♪♪
DONNA: Duff was a customer.
I think I'd seen him maybe
a couple of times,
and when Guy and Duff
got together,
it was on.
Can't live on cupcakes alone,
can you?
[ Chuckles ]
Well...
Oh!
♪♪
He's new
to the show.
Did you just eat
my sandwich.
-Mm-hmm.
-I think so.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
Pit beef, it's like
a roast-beef sandwich.
It's a bottom round flat
cooked over charcoal.
Is it always
the bottom round?
Yes.
Straight on the grill,
just like it is.
Can you get part medium rare
and part well done?
Here.
Yeah, yeah.
You can get whatever you want.
Fold it rare.
Bring it over the edge,
cut it.
Look at that!
And now in
about 15 minutes,
you're ready to start
working that.
What are
we gonna make first?
We'll make
a beef sandwich.
Now, what do you like
to put on these?
BOB: Onions,
Maybe a little salt pepper.
Little horseradish on there.
I'll take it easy on you.
[ Fieri whistles ]
♪♪
Mmm!
Ugh!
That will just clean you
right out, won't it?
Wow.
In Baltimore, people
love their horseradish.
It dates back to the beginning
stages of pit beef,
when they would top it
with raw grated horseradish.
I mean,
that meat is just --
With that horseradish
on there, mmm!
It's all about the meat.
Right.
Okay. Now, how else
do you eat this?
♪♪
I think we should have it
every single way
you can possibly make it.
My favorite is
the bulldog.
That is the sub roll,
couple of slices of cheese.
Hot Italian sausage.
Put the beef on.
Look at that,
Yeah, salt and pepper,
the horseradish --
the whole giddy-up again.
If that's what's in it.
Put a sauce on it?
You might want to try barbecue.
If the horseradish
was too strong for you,
you could try it cut --
No, no, no.
Just because I cried
through half the interview,
it wasn't too strong.
It was still enjoyable.
[ Laughter]
You're doing this
open finger thing, Duff.
Let me show you.
Get up underneath it, like this.
Bring your shoulders...
Protect yourself
when you're at the counter.
You come into my town
and teach me how to bulldog?
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: I didn't think the
pit beef could get any better.
That little sausage kicker,
mmm!
The pit beef and the bulldog
are still on the menu,
always will be.
We also have
the Baltimore Bad Boy Club.
This is my favorite sandwich.
It's amazing, and I would
suggest it to anyone.
Our Baltimore Bad Boy Club
is just a fun play
on a club sandwich.
To steal a name from Guy,
he had a show called
"Guy's Big Bite,"
where he did the Baltimore
Bad Boy Beef Sandwich.
Hope you're okay
with that, guy.
I made it --
Of course I agree!
BOB: We have
a bottom round flat here.
Our barbecue rub is paprika,
garlic, thyme,
cumin, chili powder,
salt and pepper,
a few other things.
Now we're ready to plop it
on the charcoal grill.
It's gonna spend a few hours
there, flipping back and forth.
And this is our pit ham.
And that's gonna spend
about an hour on the grill,
rolling around,
get a nice char on the outside.
The Baltimore Bad Boy Club
is gonna be 4 ounces of beef
and 4 ounces of the ham.
We're going to put them
back on the pit,
put a nice helping of our bacon,
get a little extra
smoky char on them
before it goes on the sandwich.
Start off with
some potato bread,
lettuce, hickory barbecue sauce,
a nice helping if pit ham,
some sliced tomatoes,
another slice of bread, bacon,
little bit of mayo,
Our famous pit beef.
And we top it off with a nice
helping of mac and cheese.
Baltimore Bad Boy Club.
I enjoyed it a bunch.
Pit beef has
a deeper smoky flavor
and it mixes with
the mac and cheese really well.
Can't be replicated.
You could go anywhere
up and down the east coast,
just can't find
a sandwich as good,
as juicy as Chaps.
WOMAN: The portions are huge!
You can kind of mix and mingle
anything that you'd like to do.
♪♪
FIERI: And coming up,
boy, did I take that to heart.
Look at the bite
outta that!
But the sandwiches
aren't the only things
blowing up around here.
Is there gonna
be a Chaps 2?
We're thinking
about it.
♪♪
FIERI: Back in 2008,
my Baltimore brother
Duff Goldman took me
to one of his local hangouts.
This is the famous Chaps?
This is Chaps.
FIERI: Look at that!
You come to Baltimore,
this is what you better see.
And if you don't,
it's not pit beef.
FIERI: And in 2011,
I was jonesing for more.
That's right --
It's round 2 of Chaps Pit Beef.
We get another call
for a visit,
and Guy popped back in.
How's business?
-Great.
-Off the hook.
You got a lot of people.
One, two, three.
There's like 10 guys
working right now.
Used to be five
before you were here.
Number-one seller.
"Triple D."
Yeah, see?
Yeah, mm-hmm.
When Guy and Duff came out,
Guy got this great idea
to make this monstrosity
of a sandwich.
Now, can I custom build
my own combo?
Oh, absolutely.
For my boy Duff.
BOB: We'll start
with the beef.
Some jalapeños down.
The horseradish.
Okay. Now we put
the ham up there.
BOB: Cut the burger in half.
Nacho cheese sauce!
I think we obviously
used everything we have
in the kitchen on that sandwich.
My brother, that.
[ Goldman laughs ]
And then --
Oh, my...
[ Laughs ]
Look at the bite
outta that!
Make sure
you don't...
lose anything.
It was pretty tasty.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh!
He goes for
a double bite!
After the show,
he asked me if we could
scale it down a little bit.
It's 4 ounces of corned beef,
4 ounces of pit beef,
and 4 ounces
of hot Italian sausage.
♪♪
Get that hand
outta there.
Need some condiments
for it?
I want some white onion.
a little bit of the horseradish
cut with some mayo.
That's the tiger sauce.
And some mustard.
Look at this.
It's like a little kid
getting ready
to blow out the candles
on the birthday cake.
♪♪
Ridiculous.
The sausage is incredible,
and the pit beef
is perfectly done.
We got everything we need here.
A nice big sandwich.
Is there gonna
be a Chaps 2.
We're thinking
about it.
FIERI: But they didn't have
to think too hard,
because in 2016...
We opened
our second location,
which is this one,
here in Aberdeen, Maryland,
and we have
two franchises,
and we'll be opening
two more franchise stores
this year.
"Triple D" blew us up.
I've made a lot
of good friends through my
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives"
experience
and one that stood out
was Mike Hardin,
who was the owner of Hodad's.
A very dear friend,
so in his memory,
we made the Boss Man Burger.
We're going to start with
an 11-ounce fresh-ground patty,
dip it in our house
barbecue sauce.
It goes on a potato roll
with bacon,
American cheese, and coleslaw,
which is a mixture of mayo,
apple cider vinegar,
white sugar,
black pepper, and salt.
Put a lid on it,
shake it up,
poured over the cabbage.
And the Boss Man, 908.
♪♪
Tender, moist.
It was delicious.
It was a lot of sandwich.
It was all I could do it
to eat it. [ Laughs ]
♪♪
Who'd have thought
32 years later,
we'd still be here
doing pit beef?
I did not ever
see that coming.
♪♪
FIERI: I'm telling
you right now,
do not let them open
in a neighborhood near you.
Everybody will weigh
100 pounds more.
I swear.
♪♪
Chicken Cordon Boom.
FIERI: But these guys
aren't the only
masters of their domain.
Here's the mole poblano.
FIERI: There are "Triple-D"
joints all over the country
that are crushing it
with their craft.
We'll be bopping in
to more places next time
on "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
Ugh!
BOB: Horseradish is doing
the trick, huh?
I just got a full
extra big hit. Wow!
It'll put hair on your chest
if you don't have any,
and it'll take it off
if you do.
Welcome to Baltimore.