Hey, there. I'm guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins,
and dives.
This trip,
We've got the bomb bird...
It's the love.
It's the chicken.
...primo pizza...
Gorgeous.
...and a whole lot
of family flavor.
This is exactly what
"Triple D" is about.
There's Grandma Good Southern
up in Oregon....
This is spot on,
and it's delicious.
...a taste-worthy
father-son brewery in Florida...
It's Mommy Bomb, dude
...and three
Oklahoma sisters...
You girls are weird.
...put personality
into their pie.
Ta-da!
-Whoo-hoo!
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Oklahoma City,
And as always on "Triple D,"
guess what?
I'm on the pizza hunt.
And I'm here about a place
where these three sisters
got a pizza joint.
And it started out
for health reasons,
but now, it's evolved
into a whole nother world,
where the pizzas are dynamite,
creative and unique.
This is
Stone Sisters Pizza.
[Indistinct] going in.
Whoo-hoo!
This pizza is the bomb.
Their flavor combinations
are insane.
Hey.
How y'all doing?
The restaurant and the sisters
are fantastic.
There's Sheli. There's Tami.
there's Traci.
FIERI: And their family biz
is all about
a healthy new take
on the crust.
Do people understand
what you're doing?
I'm give them
my spelt spiel.
Spelt as
an ancient grain.
And when you sprout a grain
like spelt,
it turns it from our bread carb
to a vegetable carb.
Your body feels like it's eating
a salad instead of a bread.
99% of the people
who eat gluten free
can have this crust.
It is like
a delicious cracker.
It's really, really good.
FIERI: This, right here,
is the sprouted spelt,
dried, and then brown.
SHELI: Yes. We're making
a pizza crust.
Bloomed yeast, warm water,
organic olive oil,
organic sugar, Celtic sea salt,
and then, some of the flour in.
You guys want to count at home
with me?
[ As The Count ]
Four.
Five scoops.
[ Laughs ]
Was that six or seven?
I counted.
I'm counting it all.
Okay. Then, we're gonna
turn it on for about 10 minutes.
We let prove,
then we roll it out.
SHELI: So, sprouted spelt dough
is denser,
so it's harder to roll out.
Very rustic,
Italian-looking.
And I'm going to dock it.
So it's gonna
cook evenly.
Now, do we
par-bake these?
About a minute.
At what temp?
450. Alright.
We're making
the Bossy Big Sister.
It has pepperoni and chicken,
tons of olives, blue cheese.
It's kind of
two meals in one,
with the pasta
and the pizza together.
Are you
the big sister?
I am. I am.
You got my pizza.
Tracy made this pizza
up herself.
She is so bossy.
But she needs to be.
She's the oldest.
Alright.
Let's see it.
Organic tomato sauce,
basil, oregano.
Got it.
Thyme, organic sugar,
dried garlic, pepper,
Celtic sea salt.
You're in OKC.
You're in Thunder Town.
Could talk about
the Celtics.
[ Laughs ]
And bay leaf.
I've never seen
that amount of bay leaf.
Well, that's why our sauce
is so good.
Come on down for
the bay-lead sauce.
Now, we're making
the chicken rub.
Onion powder, powdered garlic,
thyme, rosemary.
Black pepper.
And then, thunder salt.
[ Laughs ]
organic chicken breast,
organic olive oil.
Toss it up.
Put it in the oven,
and cook it
for about 20 minutes.
With sprout spelt, you want to
put the cheese on first.
Local Lovera cheese.
That is delicious cheese.
Then, we're gonna
put the sauce on.
Yellow bells,
sliced mushrooms,
red onion, black olive,
that chicken that we made.
I'm gonna go out
and change the oil,
and rotate the tires
on my car.
You just keep
working on this.
And the pepperoni.
We're done.
Voila.
450, 10 minutes.
We're gonna
make the pasta.
You girls are weird.
Put some olive oil.
Organic, by the way.
Garlic, yellow bell, red onion,
black olive, some mushrooms.
We have a special pasta.
Let me guess.
Made by magic elves.
Close. It's einkorn pasta --
gluten friendly.
The red sauce.
Ready to put on top
for our pizza.
Add the blue cheese.
It's going back in the oven
until it's finished.
Here how crunchy that is?
I want to see this crust
hold up.
It defies science.
You have great flavors.
You have this pepperoni,
and the marriage of the chicken.
The fresh vegetable side,
really good cheese.
The foundation of it all being
that crust is dynamite.
I hate when
something like this
is gonna get categorized
as a "healthy pizza."
It's just a good pizza
as it stands.
Bossy Big Sister out.
It's just delicious.
I never thought about putting
pasta on a pizza.
WOMAN: You'd think,
"Carbs, carbs, carbs.'
But this, I feel like
I could have more than
I normally would, and still
feel good about myself.
-Bratty Little Sister going in.
-Right?
Every single pie is named
for some event in their lives.
SHELI:
Front Yard Rumble.
It was quite a Thanksgiving
that time.
[ Laughter ]
They're just
so much fun.
Look at that.
Whoo!
What's the name of this pizza
we're making?
Vegan Schmegan Number 2.
This is the cashew
cream sauce.
First, we got sugar water, lemon
juice, Worcestershire sauce,
mustard, garlic cloves,
capers, our soaked cashews,
thunder sea salt.
Some thunder sea salt.
I'm gonna slowly add olive oil.
You're gonna love it.
It's almost into
a really zesty garlic alfredo.
What else
are we gonna make?
Arugula walnut pesto.
Garlic, and oil.
Next up, the arugula.
There we go.
Lemon juice.
And the thunder sea salt.
And we'll
put it together.
Take our cashew cream sauce,
nutritional yeast,
vegan cheese,
poached garlic,
spinach, artichoke, mushrooms,
tomatoes, pesto.
So much fun.
Into the 457 oven?
Yes.
Put some truffle oil on it.
-Ta-da!
-Whoo-hoo!
Our gravel
that we make --
dried onion, dried garlic,
and black pepper.
Fantastic.
♪♪
It's delicious.
Everything I'm putting on there
has such great flavor.
You get the
cheesy creaminess.
You get the richness
of the pesto.
You get the hebaciousness
from that arugula,
a little bit of that extra kick
from the gravel that you put on.
It's a delicious pizza.
Happens to be vegan.
Right.
Your Vegan Schmegan
Number 2.
Wow. This is something
I'll probably come back,
and order again.
I think it's as good as anything
you can get out there.
The three sisters
will probably kick you out
if you stay too long?
I don't know.
They might just lock the door,
and give you another beer,
If you want to take
your taste buds to Flavor Town,
then this is it.
This is exactly
what "Triple D" is about.
Real deal people
making real deal food
with a real deal reason.
Great job.
FIERI: Up next, down home
cooking in Portland, Oregon.
Oh, my goodness.
I know.
...starring and knock-out
chicken sandwich...
I have to go over yonder.
Otherwise I'm gonna die.
...and a Southern standard
with a not-so-standard
ingredient.
If you want to have
a really good hushpuppy,
this is your hushpuppy.
♪♪
So, I'm here on the northeast
side of Portland, Oregon,
and I'm looking for
this Southern joint
like you'd find
in the South --
scratch-making
the biscuits,
the chicken and dumplings,
the fried chicken.
But the funny thing is,
is I'm looking for the place.
It's in an old defunct bakery
called Delphina's.
And they say, when you find
the Delphina's bakery side,
well, you know
you're there.
And they say
it's over yonder.
Oh, wait a second. That's
the name of the restaurant.
This is Yonder.
♪♪
Large chicken and dumplings,
table 3.
It's like good
down-home cooking.
Everything made
from scratch.
I got your North Carolina
country ham plate.
It's the true
Southern experience.
It has the taste,
but it also has the hospitality.
FIERI: That's because
chef and owner Maya Lovelace
has planted her real deal,
Southern roots
deep into this
Northwestern joint.
Where are you from?
-Beaufort, North Carolina.
LOVELACE: The reason I wanted
to name the place "Yonder"
is because "yonder" is
"that place over there."
It's kind of me being homesick
for the South.
SERVER:
I got your dusted wing plate.
MAN: I tell people
it's like Southern food,
but not like
they've ever had before.
MAN #2: It's the love.
It's the chicken.
There's your tag line --
"It's the love.
It's the chicken."
Alright. I got a dipped
Intimidator ready to roll.
I had the
Intimidator today,
and it's gone
because it's delicious.
The chicken is really fried
and crispy.
Super well-balanced.
You've got the bacon jam,
pimento cheese.
The zucchini pickles have
a little bit of zip,
a little sweetness.
Do you work here,
or do you just eat here?
[ Laughs ]
We're doing our Intimidator
chicken sandwich,
which is named after
Dale Earnhardt.
Wait, wait, wait.
You're a NASCAR fan?
A little bit.
It's in my blood.
So, the first thing that
we're making here is the bun.
It's a Japanese
milk bread style.
Buttermilk, flour,
and water.
Alright.
So, we cook this down.
And that's what gives structure
to the bun.
If I was making some kid
Play-Doh funky goo,
that would be it.
More buttermilk eggs,
sugar --
which gives it a nice
little sweetness, obviously.
Does this mean "sweetness"
in Southern cooking?
I do this for everything.
Instant yeast,
benne seeds --
which is basically what we use
instead of sesame --
bread flour.
We let this mix.
Portion it. Bake it at 350
for about 20 minutes.
Wait a second.
This is a new one.
This is "about."
We're going to move on to
our chicken.
Boneless, skin-on chicken thighs
shows the Southern side of it.
Yeah.
Buttermilk, hot sauce, and salt.
That's it.
Okay, so this brines
for three hours.
What are we dredging
this in?
AP flour, stone ground
white cornmeal, rice flour,
salt and pepper.
And then,
fry it at 350?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, so we're making
our western North Carolina style
dip sauce.
Got it.
Apple cider vinegar, ketchup,
Worcester sauce.
Worcester sauce?
I thought that was how
you pronounced it properly.
Worcestershire sauce.
Sorghum molasses
is next.
Stone ground mustard,
brown sugar, garlic powder,
cayenne, salt, black pepper,
whole cloves, and then water.
So, once that
simmer reduces.
Then, we'll strain it,
blend it,
just to make
the texture silky.
Last piece.
Bacon jam.
We start with
really smoky bacon,
which we get
from Tennessee.
It's like a campfire.
[ Stammers ]
Camp...
fire.
So, we go into
a cold pan.
Because it gives you a chance
to render that fat out
before that meat
starts to seize up.
There's your little
cooking tip for today.
You dig it?
So, now, we're gonna go in
with our onion, garlic,
chili flake,
mustard seeds, bay leaf.
And then, once that's nice,
and translucent,
and beautiful,
add in...
Apple cider vinegar,
brown sugar.
Just remove the bay leaf
for service.
Exactly. So, we have
our toasted bun, here.
Bacon jam.
Pimento cheese --
which we make here, as well.
Fried chicken thigh, here,
in the sauce,
iceberg lettuce, 'cause I think
it's just classic.
It's old-school.
Bread and butter pickles,
which me make with zucchini.
Zucchini?
Yeah.
I like the texture
and the flavor.
You're the boss.
Top bun.
And then, decoration.
Decoration.
It's gorgeous.
Look yonder.
♪♪
It's fantastic.
The crumb on this bun,
it's light.
It has texture.
And the fried chicken,
it's not a bunch of batter
and a little bit of chicken.
Nice crunch to it.
A fantastic North Carolina
barbecue sauce,
with a good
vinegar punch.
Pimento's dynamite.
Bacon jam's on point.
And that zucchini pickles
all play their game.
I have to go
over yonder.
Otherwise,
I'm gonna die.
[ Laughs ]
Alright. I've got your
Intimidator sandwich, here.
It's tangy.
It is delicious.
It is completely unique.
There is no other fried chicken
in Portland,
as far as I'm concerned.
Alright. I got a Gutsy
Catfish hot up here. Ready.
Where did you learn
to cook, by the way?
From my parents
and my grandmother.
Lillie Mae Abernathy-Lovelace.
That's, like,
the whole alphabet.
I feel like
Southern grandmas
have to have, like,
four or five names.
Is that your grandma's picture
up there on the counter?
That is actually
someone else's grandma.
We kind of collect
grandma photos.
But my grandma
is part of the gallery.
I've just got to do
one more bite for science.
I love it.
-Ugh, this old girl.
-Come on.
FIERI:
You're not that old.
I was talking about
the mixer.
Excuse me.
She came to play.
I'm playing.
Welcome back, partner.
How'd that sound?
It was great.
Do we say "partner"
in North Carolina?
Not really, but that's fine.
Not so much.
But we're at Yonder.
Chef Maya hanging out
in Portland, Oregon.
We're having some
dynamite food.
You chicken
and dumplings. Enjoy.
Yonder is a very
special restaurant
featuring a bunch of stuff
from the South.
WOMAN: Maya takes, like,
old classics,
and she puts
a creative twist on them.
Alright. I got catpuppies up,
ready to roll.
These are
catfish hushpuppies.
This beautiful,
pillowed, doughy,
fantastic fried fritter.
So, the hushpuppy by itself
isn't good enough.
We're gonna add catfish to it.
Exactly.
It's a Tennessee
wild catfish.
Bring it.
Awesome.
We are gonna just do
a quick cure on this.
A little sugar,
and a little salt.
So, then, me go in
with our sweet onion,
eggs, buttermilk,
stone ground cornmeal,
garlic powder, baking powder,
black pepper, salt,
onion powder, sugar,
bourbon barrel smoked paprika,
and cayenne pepper.
It's a nice
thick batter.
That gives us
a little puff.
To the fryer, 350.
Yep. Four minutes.
That's it.
Easy peezy.
And what does this
get served with?
Our Comeback sauce.
So, we start with
our mayonnaise --
another crucial
Southern ingredient --
our house-fermented chili paste,
hot sauce, ketchup,
stone ground mustard,
lemon juice.
This is a bourbon barrel
smoked soy sauce,
paprika,
garlic powder,
salt, and good old-fashioned
black pepper.
Mix this up.
It's ready to go.
So, we have our hushpuppies --
golden brown and crispy.
We are gonna finish this
with a little spice mix
that we make with salt,
a little bit of sugar, paprika,
cayenne, and citric acid.
And you want to do that
while they're still warm,
so the seasoning adheres.
Exactly.
How many in an order?
We do 8.
Oh, my goodness.
I know.
We finish these chives.
And then, we also serve it
with whipped sorghum butter,
which is sweet.
Serve them up with
the Comeback sauce.
Gorgeous.
♪♪
When you look at
that nice crust...
Great crunch.
This is not
your average hushpuppy.
it's tender.
It's not overcooked.
It's not fishy in any means,
but it does add moisture to it.
It does add texture to it.
It does add flavor to it.
You can go to the sweet side
of it with the sorghum butter.
You can go to savory side of it
with the Comeback.
If you've never had
a hushpuppy
or if you want to have
a really good hushpuppy,
This is your hushpuppy.
Excellent job.
Thank you.
Catfish hushpuppies with
Comeback sauce for dipping.
WOMAN: Super crispy
on the outside,
really flaky
on the inside.
It's delicious.
Instead of overspicing
the catfish,
she puts the spice
in the Comeback sauce,
so you keep on dipping it in
there, and coming back.
We are ready to go out the door
to table 1. Order up.
WOMAN #2: Visitors in Portland
that come to Yonder
are gonna have a great time
no matter what they order.
This is a little bit
more special,
a little bit
more personal.
And you could really
taste that.
You're a fantastic
ambassador.
You're showing folks
this is how it's done.
This is spot on,
and it's delicious.
Thank you so much.
Well done.
Thank you.
FIERI:
Coming up, a killer kitchen
at a Dania Beach brewery...
You're gonna gain weight
hanging out with this guy.
...whipping up
wild wings...
I'm ripping it off.
I'm taking it home.
...and topping Florida flavor
onto the crust.
We're breaking a lot of
traditional Italian rules, here.
I'm not Italian.
♪♪
Love coming down
to South Florida.
Now, this is one of my favorite
areas, Dania Beach.
I used to come down here
all the time
to check out
the highlight.
Remember "Miami Vice," the guy
throwing the ball, the basket,
the whole thing?
Anyhow.
So, I'm down here to check out
this brewery
doing outstanding beer --
I mean,
some real unique stuff.
But they're also not
overshadowing their restaurant.
No. They've got
a chef-driven concept
where they're doing
wood-fired pizzas
and wings
you've never heard of.
This is
3 Sons Brewing Co.
Walking in.
Pork sandwich.
This place was built on
a foundation of the beer.
Now, they're becoming
world-renowned for their food.
Steak bahn mi.
They make you feel like you're
at home, like it's a family.
That's 'cause for co-founders
Corey Artanis
and his dad, Joe,
this place really is family.
They even named the joint
after Corey's boys.
-Do they work?
-Not yet.
Child labor laws.
FIERI: But they're putting chef
Nicolay Adinaguey to work.
How did you get involved
in this?
I like beer.
If that's the job application,
I can work here, too.
Nicolay had met with me before
at, like, different beer events.
I automatically just wanted,
like, wood fire.
All wood fuel.
Yeah.
the dashi wings.
MAN:
The wings aren't fried.
They're cooked in
the wood oven.
Very unique.
Falls off the bone.
I usually go for two rounds.
-What are we making?
-Chicken wings.
Organic. No hormone's.
-Got it.
Salt, cracked black pepper.
So, these will get dropped
in the oven, what temp?
500 degrees
for 24 minutes.
And what's the sauce
we're gonna make for these?
We're gonna do
a dashi butter.
Do most people, when they read
the menu and see "dashi butter,"
do they get it?
Now they do.
We start by boiling
a little bit of water.
Dashi pellets, sea kelp,
and smoked bonito.
Salted butter, fresh thyme,
choyu white soy.
Although it doesn't
look white.
Mirin, some garlic,
xanthan gum,
Tighten it all up.
I'm sorry, can I
have that as a soup?
What made you
think of that?
I went to
a restaurant.
I've been to
a restaurant, too.
It didn't make me
think of that.
I'm ripping it off.
I'm taking it home.
It's umami bomb, dude.
Yeah.
What's up next, Chef?
Our wasabi aioli.
Mayo, white soy --
choyu -- mirin,
Wasabi.
Toasted sesame.
And then,
a bunch of lemon juice.
A little whisk.
Delicious.
After we've cooked our wings,
we're going to throw them
in the pizza oven
for about 3 to 5 minutes.
Maybe we'll
sing a song, then.
[ Vocalizes ]
Didn't see that
coming, folks.
Get these out
of the oven.
We'll work the
dashi butter into it.
Into our bowl.
Wasabi aioli, chilies,
and scallions.
Nice little drumette.
Not too big.
Not too small.
There's meat on it.
And it's probably hard
for you to imagine,
I've had a few wings
in my life.
See how polite?
He didn't look at my gut.
This is an elevated wing.
This is something I would put up
against the great wings
of deep fried
and specialty sauces.
Dude, I'm 1000%
ripping it off.
I mean, like,
ripping it off to the point
where I'm gonna probably
take this, and these.
Start the car.
♪♪
-The dashi wings.
-I like the wasabi aioli.
Nice little spice,
but not overpowering,
It's not fried,
but it's still crispy.
I know you've never
had a wing before,
but it's that something
that comes off a chicken.
What's a chicken?
It's just delicious, man.
Alright. Dropping in.
Chef has reminded me
of a buddy of mine,
and I had
to call him.
Chef Adam Richman,
Chef Nicolay.
You tell me if these two
are not brothers.
RICHMAN: It's our burden, being
this good-looking, Nicolay.
Hey...
[ Laughs ]
MAN:
Nicolay's amazing.
Whatever he does
back there,
it just blows
your mind every time.
Favorite thing
on the menu?
WOMAN: I love
the shrimp pizza.
-Shrimp pizza up.
-It's just so good.
The shrimp pops.
The cheese just oozes
in your mouth.
Thin crust,
capers on top.
You can't stop
eating it.
What's the pie
we're gonna make today?
Shrimp pie.
So it's small?
No.
We're gonna make
our pizza dough.
Yeast, the water,
olive oil, flour.
Mix this
for six minutes.
FIERI: Got it.
Then, it's going to rest
for 15 minutes.
Then, we're gonna
hit it with the salt.
You spin for
6 minutes again.
Pull it out.
Rest for 30.
Portion. And bulk ferment
for three to five days.
You're gonna gain weight
hanging out with this guy.
So, this is
the vinaigrette?
Correct. Dijon, shallots,
thyme, sherry vinegar, garlic,
some lemon juice,
extra virgin olive oil.
Where are we at?
I just build my crust.
Fresh escarole.
Didn't see that coming.
A little manchego.
Fresh mozz.
We use these really pretty
Gulf pink shrimp.
And what did we marinate
these in, Chef?
Just extra virgin olive oil
and some oregano.
Now, we're ready
to get in the oven.
We're 800, 850,
two to three minutes.
Yes, sir.
Gorgeous.
Garlic confit, capers,
vinaigrette, Pecorino Romano,
oregano, crushed red pepper,
Maldon sea salt.
Short of
the kitchen sink,
I think we got everything
on there, Chef.
♪♪
We're breaking a lot of
traditional Italian rules, here.
I'm not Italian.
Good point.
I'll just eat it,
and shut up.
With That beautiful shrimp
on there,
I think the escarole is
a great supporting player.
The saltiness of the manchego,
the saltiness of the Pecorino.
But the real key, Chef,
is the dough.
I'd eat the dough
by itself.
Well done.
Watch out for this guy.
-Shrimp pizza.
-The manchego cheese
with the capers
just blends so well.
Holly and Dave
are friends of mine,
we share a common interest
in the Best Buddies program,
supporting intellectually
disabled adults and kids.
What do you think?
I wasn't sure about the shrimp
on the pizza, but wow.
It's bursting
with flavor.
So, I think
I'm converting.
-It's so good.
-Tuna tacos.
Once you come
to 3 Sons,
you're never gonna want
to stop coming.
I know the beer here
is dynamite,
and often the kitchen
plays the second fiddle.
But what you guys have here
are dueling banjos.
Well done.
-Thank you.
That's it for this week.
But don't you worry.
I'll be looking for more joints
all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
Punch it down
a few times.
How do we do that?
We punch it.
She's very animated.
There's a lot of this,
a lot of that.
And don't want to
get in her way.
This one is a wildcat.