I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
O-M-G.
We're going from
standout seafood...
It looks too pretty
to eat, Chef,
...to saucy Sicilian..
Thank you, folks.
I'll be here all week.
Try the meatballs
...like in a wood-fired food
truck in Oklahoma City...
That's a good-looking pie
and a true off-the-hook
haven in Portland.
If you want to make it,
you can do it.
You can do it.
How do you want to do it?
Plus, the one and only
Vanilla Ice is chillin'
with me in Florida...
Ooh!
Mmm!
...for a swashbuckling
culinary adventure.
Tastes good, looks good,
smells good. It is good.
That's all right here, right now
on Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives.
♪♪
So I'm here in Fort Lauderdale,
Florida, and I got this buddy.
And he says, "Next time
you come into town..."
Hey, man, check this out.
Aw, dude, that's awesome.
Anyhow, he says, "Next time
you come into town,
you've got to find
a great seafood restaurant
because I'm a, uh --"
What are you again?
I'm a vegaquarium.
It means he only eats
vegetables and seafood.
Ladies and gentlemen, the one
and only Vanilla Ice.
Dude, what are you,
stuck in the '90s?
I'm always stuck
in the '90s.
The best decade ever, man.
This is Pirate Republic.
♪♪
Whole snapper going in.
They have amazing food here.
Everything's
always so fresh.
Ba-ba-ba. Order up.
There's a lot
of Brazilian influence
and there's a lot of influence
from all around the world.
FIERI:
That global flavor was picked up
by Brazilian-born owners
Roberto and Claudia Guerios
during their many
high seas adventures.
We sailed -- Yeah.
We sailed most of our life
on the Caribbean
on the pirate ship.
You have a real
pirate ship?
Oh, yeah.
Argh!
That is cool.
So you summoned
your like inner pirate energy
and applied it here.
-Yeah.
-And where did the recipes
come from?
Around the Caribbean.
Venezuela. Brazil.
Here's your
seafood moqueca.
Seafood moqueca
is one of my favorites.
It's Brazilian style
seafood stew.
It's got clams
and it's got calamari
and it's got mussels and shrimp.
Just really,
really nice presentation.
What's the dish
we're gonna make?
The moqueca.
And what is a moqueca?
It's a seafood stew.
Okay.
Okay, here is
our golden corvina.
Are you good at
filleting fish?
No.
When you are from Florida,
to graduate like kindergarten,
you had to be able
to filet a fish.
That's probably the
last time I did it.
Here he goes. Look at her
boning out the fish.
And you were not a chef
before all of this happened?
Mnh-mnh.
You just learned
the hard way?
Yeah. Skin it and chop it.
Great. What else
is going to be in this?
We are going to make
the pepper sauce
that I use in the moqueca.
Okay.
Those are my biquino pepper.
Bode pepper.
That would be goat.
That's a goat pepper?
[ Imitates goat ]
Goat pepper.
You really got a problem
if it's a ghost pepper.
What's that one?
O tipo de doce.
But translate to lady fingers.
That's a lot of spicy.
Go ahead, try that one.
You like spice?
I love spice.
And this is the malagueta,
which is also known
as peri-peri.
Very nice.
Little touch of salt.
A little touch of pepper.
In goes olive oil.
Hit it up.
Now try that.
Ooh, that's real good.
Now we're getting into building
the base of the sauce.
Correct.
This is blended oil,
garlic, a little onion,
bay leaf, salt, pepper,
our housemade
pepper sauce.
That's as much as you put in?
It's like two tablespoons.
You made all that
for that little?
Oh, we use it a lot
in other dishes, too.
Ahh.
Okay.
Bell peppers.
Bell peppers go in.
You guys cook
at home a lot?
It's a challenge when you start
to do the veg cooking
because
you got so many
different flavors
and spices
you can throw around.
It's all about
how you prepare it.
Pureed tomatoes.
Yes.
And this will cook down
for how much longer, Chef?
About half an hour.
Got it.
Alright, chef,
let's get into this.
The moqueca sauce
we just made,
corvina, shrimp, clams.
Salt, pepper.
This is dende oil
from a palm tree.
Okay.
And it's
traditionally used
in this dish.
And coconut milk.
Then we cover the pan.
I feel terrible, too.
We've got to make Rob one.
You going to make
one for me?
I guess we could share.
He'll get one bite
and one bite only.
Then we add calamari
and mussels.
Soon as they pop,
we're ready to rock.
Look at that. There's a lot
of seafood in this.
Smells delish.
See what we got here,
brother.
Oooh!
Mmm!
Isn't that dynamite?
Everything is cooked right,
not overcooked.
I love the kick.
That's really good taste.
Tastes a little Creole almost.
It's spicy.
It's tangy.
The kicker to the whole thing
is the coconut milk.
That's what gives it that
luxurious,
that creamy, that silkiness.
It's fantastic.
Now this is where
the friendship's gonna kinda
get into
a different realm.
Pull it back over here.
No, let's just
bring it right back over here.
Wait a minute.
[ Laughs ]
Seafood moqueca.
I love a good variety
of seafoods in it.
It's beautiful. It's colorful
and it makes you want to eat it.
The texture of the calamari
is exceptional.
Nice and tender.
Yes.
I'm tasting like a creamy,
like a curry kind of thing.
But you like it?
Oh, yeah, it's wonderful.
Is every seafood restaurant
like this in Florida?
Is everybody on the water
or is this special?
It's definitely special.
You get the nice air
off of the water.
MAN: You can come in the boat
and just dock
right in front of the restaurant
and have a great time.
That's my favorite.
We're going to go
to commercial.
When we come back,
another fantastic dish.
We have the whole snapper
with escovitch.
So tender and juicy
and flavorful.
Just something very special
that you don't get everywhere.
This is going to
stay over here.
Okay.
Go check your car.
I can see the lounge act
and like the maintenance guy
at the same time.
Lounge, maintenance
and souvenir shop
attendee.
I'm in. I need to fill out
an application.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Welcome back.
Triple-D hanging out
in Fort Lauderdale, Florida,
with my buddy Rob Van Winkle.
We're hanging out
at Pirate Republic.
Chef Claudia and her husband
traveled all through
the Caribbean
and ended up opening up
this funky little joint
covered in decks on the water,
really dynamite seafood.
Bacalao with octopus.
Every day there's fresh fish.
It's the freshest in town.
And their food
is always delicious.
It definitely reminds me
of the Caribbean.
FIERI: So it makes sense that a
Jamaica classic is on the menu.
WOMAN: Whole snapper
with escovitch.
The escovitch on top of it
adds a really nice brightness.
Fresh like it just jumped out
of the water onto the plate.
What's the next dish?
Escovitch.
Which is a Jamaican topping
for fried fish.
Everybody has their way
of doing it.
There you go.
White vinegar. Onions.
Okay.
You're gonna pickle this a
little bit in the vinegar.
Bell peppers, pimento berries
or allspice berries.
A nice little
scotch bonnet.
You put that all in there!
Correct.
Good morning.
[ Laughs ]
I always find it fascinating.
It's not just the ingredients.
It's also how you cook
each ingredient
and what placement
each one of them goes in.
There's a lot of chemistry
there that confuses me.
Let's get into this.
Alright.
So this is our snapper.
Been scaled?
Yeah.
So now you get to eat
the skin as well.
The key to scoring this open
like that
is the fact that you're going
to be able to create
a lot of texture
inside of the fish.
Then the presentation
will be amazing.
It's gonna be out of bounds.
Salt, pepper.
Drop this at 350 degrees?
About seven minutes.
Got it. Ooh.
Here you go.
The other side
will be Rob's side.
Because that's the better side,
right?
That's -- Exactly.
That's how I take care of
my friend.
Smell those peppers
and onions.
I'm begging for
a tortilla right now.
Going Baja fish-taco style?
[ba-ha]
I believe it's Baja.
[ba-jah]
[ Laughs ]
Baja?
It looks too pretty to eat,
Chef.
Take a picture of it
before you eat.
Yeah, you do need
to take a picture of it.
Ready?
Now that's money. Whoo!
It's a work of art.
It's not hot.
♪♪
Mm!
Mmm.
Nice little crunch
of the fry of the fish.
Sweet.
Mmm!
You get the crisp in there,
but you get the sautéed
vegetables
just poppin' with flavor.
You got to think when it fries,
it seals in all that moisture.
And I think
it's being enhanced
by the pickling
of the escovitch.
You're getting all that acid
coming through.
Tastes good. Looks good.
Smells good. It is good.
Here's your snapper.
It's got a crispy outside.
Beautiful, soft, white,
flaky fish inside.
And are they doing it
in traditional Jamaican style?
Yes.
One of the closest.
Which is why we
keep coming back.
Got the seafood moqueca.
FIERI: It's not just
a themed pirate restaurant,
it's a real-deal restaurant
that just happens
to have a pirate theme.
Absolutely.
Don't tell too many people
because we want to keep it
a secret.
It's delicious.
It's straightforward.
It's real. It's legit.
CLAUDIA: Thank you.
You delivered.
You happy?
I'm happy.
Nicely done, Chef.
Thank you. Rob,
you're the best, man.
Thank you, brother.
Gotta love that.
♪♪
FIERI:
Up next in Oklahoma City...
Time to make
the magic happen.
...a joint wheeling
and dealing the pie...
I mean, it's just
really delicious.
...topped with a family tie.
We're not open yet.
Making grandma's sauce.
Hold on.
People are getting
all antsy-dancey out there.
♪♪
I'm here at OKC for a little
pizza in the parking lot.
Now, this ain't just your
regular old pizza truck.
No, this thing
is a monster.
And the oven?
Not any regular old oven.
No, it's wood fired.
And the recipes?
Well, they're not your
everyday recipes
'cause they're handed down
from generations.
This is the Saucee Sicilian.
Tusa coming out, Nonna.
My favorite.
MAN: Some of the best pizza
in Oklahoma City,
and I stand by that.
-I got this.
-It's hot. It's fresh.
And the flavors are on point.
FIERI: And on four wheels.
Ever since Gannon Mendez
left the corporate world
to open a food truck.
Tusa. Palermo!
He wanted the best help
he could find.
So he asked his mom,
Priscilla.
She was living in
the mountains in Colorado.
And I'm like,
"Hey, I need you on Oklahoma.
Let's start a food truck."
He got me out
of retirement.
O-M-G.
You went...
Old-school Italian,
just like my great grandmother.
Decided to use her recipes.
Tripani coming out.
Yum.
The tripani pizza
is outstanding.
It's got the prosciutto,
it's got the figs,
it's got some balsamic,
and the wood fire
that they do
in there is amazing.
Alright,
let's get into this.
We are making
our dough from scratch.
A high gluten flour.
Got it.
Salt, water, and yeast.
So traditional pizza
dough recipe.
Mix for six, seven minutes.
Put it in a tub. Let it proof.
This is my great
grandma's blanket.
Really?
So it's like
grandma's blessing.
And we're going to
do eight ounce balls.
How good are you
at the portion game?
How good are you?
Eh.
Where you think you're
at with that one?
8.6.
Do your picks.
8.4.
Bam.
8.0. Was it three cuts?
Or four cuts?
Goes by the amount of cuts.
8.8.
Ooh!
7.6.
That's under.
We never want to go under.
There's 8.1.
I got it in three.
You got it in four. But I mean,
I'm not saying I'm better.
I'm just saying that --
Three cuts, I believe.
Go back to the tape.
Then that proofs
for three days.
Yes, sir.
So you're getting that nice,
big,
yeasty flavored dough.
Yeah.
Alright, Chef. Next up?
-Alright,
we're going to do
our balsamic maple glaze.
Okay.
Balsamic vinegar.
Bring it to a boil,
once it reduces down,
we're gonna go with
some pure maple syrup.
Give it a little
extra sweet.
That's it.
Time to make
the magic happen.
Alright, we're going to do
a little Caputo.
Can't argue that
that's hand-thrown.
Ricotta cheese with whole milk,
mozzarella, some fresh figs,
I figured.
Roasted garlic.
We like to put a lot on it.
Roasted red pepper.
Beautiful.
And we'll slide it
in the oven.
90 seconds. And what kind of
wood are we using in the oven?
Pecan hickory.
Easy peasy.
But gives so svelte.
[ Laughs ]
Cut it up here real quick.
Top each slice with prosciutto.
Turn it one time
to the left.
My mother says that
is her superstition.
The balsamic maple glaze.
Drizzle it over.
That's a
good-looking pie.
♪♪
I mean,
it's just really delicious.
The crust is the foundation,
and it's out of balance.
Neapolitan pizza
has to be in balance.
And you give good portions,
a good amount of prosciutto.
It's an honest pizza --
scratch-made, handmade,
with a lot of
family love in it.
Well done.
Look.
-Pizza for Kim.
-Thank you.
The crust is very
soft and crunchy.
The figs were
delicious.
The balsamic glaze
is fantastic.
He always has the biggest line
of all the truck places.
FIERI: And some days,
it even includes the mayor.
Your food scene
is blowing up.
The culinary scene
is a big part
of creating a culture
and a place that --
That's why
he's mayor.
We have to have
great food.
Keep it up, man.
You're leading
a great community.
Yeah. Well,
call the mayor
if you get into any trouble
while you're here.
That's exactly
what I needed.
-Thanks for coming in today.
-What's going on?
If you told somebody
to come here,
what should they have
when they come here?
Nonna's Meatballs.
The meatballs
are the must-have?
I would agree with that.
Nonna's Sauce
and Meatballs.
Nonna literally does her best,
with the marinara,
the fresh grated Parmesan,
and the big basil leave.
Some of the best sauce
and meatballs.
What are we making?
MENDEZ: My mother's
homemade meatballs.
This is my
great-grandmother's recipe.
50/50 pork and beef.
We'll mix this together.
Add some eggs.
Can't have enough garlic.
Grandma was right
on point, with that.
My mother's homemade
bread crumbs,
parsley,
and the Parmesan cheese.
Okay. You mix these up.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Got to get
working, dude.
We got a lot to do,
and a line of people.
Go, rock, go.
We're a team.
We're gonna roast them
in the oven.
Next up, we have my
great-grandma's marinara sauce.
We'll do a little
olive oil.
One short rib.
Once it's seared up, then we're
gonna just take it out.
Why?
That's the way
Grandma Lina would do it.
We'll add it
back in.
Garlic. Onions.
Get it cooked down.
We're not open yet.
We're making
Grandma's sauce.
Hold on.
People are getting
all antsy dancey out there.
Tomato paste, tomato sauce,
two cans of water in.
Wait a second. When did
the bird come into play?
The bird?
The toucan.
Thank you, folks.
I'll be here all week.
Try the meatballs.
The short rib goes back in.
Sugar, salt,
the red pepper flake,
black pepper,
four bay leaves.
Bring that to a boil.
Let it simmer.
And then, we're gonna
put the meatballs in it.
Really?
Yes, sir.
It cooks for about
another eight hours.
You putting it in
a double cup?
A little Parm.
Top if off with
a basil leaf.
Look at that.
Mmm. Delicious, and tender,
and moist.
Great sauce.
The little sprinkle of the
Parmesan right at the end.
That fresh basil...
hits that sauce,
and just blooms.
And that's a good amount
of garlic.
I'm telling you,
Grandma taught you right.
Great job, sir.
-Thank you. I appreciate it.
Watch out for
this guy.
Nonna's Sauce
and Meatballs.
-Thanks.
-Thank you.
Just an authentic taste
that I can't get enough of.
I usually would
have to have a straw
to get that sauce out of there,
I love it so much.
-Okay, Nick.
-Right here.
MAN: It's just a warm place
to come in.
It's not Just
about the food.
You know,
they're great people, as well.
Congratulations.
I appreciate it.
For a dude that's not from
the restaurant business,
and with the backing of the mom,
you just can't go wrong.
Right? Thank you, man.
Perfect.
Nice to meet you, Mom.
Nice to meet
you, sweetheart.
FIERI: Coming up in Portland,
Oregon...
this is the kind of place
everybody wants
to have in their
neighborhood.
...a spot stepping up
the seafood...
I don't know whether to
eat it or get in it.
...and casting out
a few surprises.
Something I didn't
see coming,
but I definitely
would eat all day -
for the rest of the week.
Starting now.
♪♪
I'm here in the southwest area
of Portland, Oregon,
to check out a place
where the chef
gave from a long background
in the corporate world.
And finally, one day, he said
he was gonna break free.
That's right. He's gonna
do things on his own terms,
do things his own way.
He's gonna cook
from his favorite seasons
and his favorite regions.
Wait a second.
I'd be a perfect name
for a restaurant.
This is Seasons and Region's
Seafood Grill.
Salmon salad on the fly.
The seafood is so fresh,
and it's always delicious.
WOMAN: There's a lot of good
mom and pops in Portland,
and this is definitely
one of them.
Is just out of this world.
FIERI:
And out of the box --
which is how chef and owner
Greg Schwab rolls.
We take the best
of the season,
and we use world
cuisine recipes.
So, what that means is that
we can do whatever we want.
If you want to make it,
you can do it.
You can do it.
MAN: He kind of
switches it up
depending on what's available,
which is pretty great.
But I haven't had a better
cioppino in Portland yet.
Cioppino with crab cake.
Pick up, please.
The fish in the cioppino
is always super fresh.
The sauce is outrageous.
It's got great spice.
It's got great
depth of flavor.
So what are we
going to make?
Northwest Seafood
Cioppino.
Okay.
We're gonna make
our cioppino broth first.
Olive oil, carrots,
onions, celery,
pureed garlic, thyme,
pepper flakes,
black pepper,
brown fennel,
marjoram, oregano,
bay leaf, kosher salt.
Next up, sugar,
red wine vinegar, red wine,
lemon juice,
basil puree.
Anchovy paste, for a little
more fish flavor, there.
Clam stock, tomato paste, diced
tomato, crushed tomato, water.
How long is this all gonna
cook down for?
Two hours.
I assume that you're able to
just mix in the seafood
that you like when you have it,
when it's fresh.
Yeah.
What are we running today?
We're going to top it with
a Dungeness crab cake.
A crab cake
goes on top.
Yes.
That I haven't seen.
Pre-cooked onions, egg,
roasted red pepper, parsley,
Tabasco for heat,
Worcestershire sauce,
Old Bay seasoning, Dijon.
And now...
Local Dungeness.
Yep.
Just a little binder
of the breadcrumbs.
Make that into one big crab cake
for me, and that'll be flamingo.
So, we're gonna give our ring
just a little spray.
Some panko, some crab,
and then panko on top.
We're gonna
pan-fry this.
Actually,
we're gonna deep-fry it.
Time to build it.
A little clarified
butter, salmon,
rockfish, salt spring mussels,
white wine, lemon juice.
Some of the cioppino base
that we built.
Fantastic.
Mussels are open.
A little more salt, pepper,
a little parsley.
It smells fantastic.
Crab cake, chive on top.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
That's really good.
That broth is fantastic.
Typically, when you
have cioppino, you know,
you'd like to have some bread,
or something, to dip it into.
And this crab cake on top
is perfectly crunchy,
which would be kind of like
the crusty bread going into it.
Works incredibly well.
Thank you, chef,
for wrecking it.
'Cause this is what
I'm gonna expect, now,
is a little salty,
crunchy crab right on top.
Something I didn't
see coming,
but I definitely
would eat all day --
for the rest of
the week.
Starting now.
We've got cioppino.
MAN: Oh, the cioppino
is good.
The crab cake
is delicious.
It's always so flavorful.
Can't be beat.
Chicken and waffle.
Pick up, please.
This is a go-to place,
because Greg knows
where to get
the best food.
Everything's super fresh
and locally sourced.
Greg actually has
some gardens,
so you get fresh
vegetables.
I've got 14 acres.
We've got four
greenhouses.
Seriously?
You're an over-achiever.
What else you got
the repertoire?
Dungeness crab leg
and spinach risotto.
Risotto coming up.
The risotto is one of the
highlights of this restaurant.
It's bright,
and colorful,
combined with
the fresh crab meat,
is just an
amazing experience.
So give me the rundown.
Okay.
Butter,
arborio rice, onion.
Next up...
Fresh thyme, black pepper,
fresh rosemary.
Chicken stock,
saffron.
White wine
in there, too.
Oh, yeah.
Was that an "oh yeah"
I just got?
That was an
"oh, yeah."
Parmesan
and butter.
Now, what are
we into.
We're gonna make
our shellfish stock
for our crab bisque.
I like it.
A little olive oil.
Carrots, diced onions, celery,
shrimp shells, crab shells.
Add chicken stock
to that.
Let this cook down
how long?
Hour and a half
to two hours.
Strain it.
Good to go for our bisque.
To that, we're gonna add
tomato paste, cayenne pepper,
black pepper guy, white pepper,
thyme, rosemary, paprika,
a little bit of fish sauce to
give it a little umami in there.
Loves his mommy.
We're gonna add a sweet rice
flour roux, brandy, cream,
throw butter at it.
Got it.
Let's see it, chef.
A little bit of butter.
Rose broker, a carrot,
caramelized onion,
roasted red pepper
our saffron risotto,
our spinach puree.
Hurry up, before I eat
all the crab.
Butter, crab legs.
That's how many crab legs
come with this order?
That's 10
crab legs.
Our risotto,
Dungeness crab legs.
There's our bisque,
blanc sauce,
and a little radish sprout
to finish.
Mangia, mangia.
I don't know whether
to eat it or get in it.
♪♪
I like the little veggie
component inside of it,
of the roasted carrots
and the caramelized onions.
We've got the spinach into the
risotto, which is really nice.
The bisque
is dynamite.
The buerre blanc really
complements the crab.
It's rich and filling,
not heavy.
I'll have two more
orders, please.
Coming right up.
SERVER: Got a Dungeness
crab leg risotto.
This risotto is incredible.
the spinach comes it, like,
a really nice undertone, there.
The crab is really fresh,
really good variety
of flavors.
Sole Parmesan.
-What do you think of the food?
-It's delicious.
It's one of my favorite
restaurants to come to.
It's Southwest Portland's
little hidden gem.
This is the kind of place
everybody wants to have
in their neighborhood.
-Thank you.
-Well done.
Was that a road trip,
or what?
But don't worry.
There's plenty more joints
all over this great country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Triple D."
All right, Mayor,
to get this straight --
to get a Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives Guy Fieri Street
here in Oklahoma City --
what's it gonna cost me?
Just our new high-speed
first-responders vehicle
Sounds good to me.
Engine 12
is en route.