People are asking me
all the time, "Hey, Guy.
That one joint
you checked out in that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how'd they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
'cause "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up.
And we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
We've got a little breakfast,
a little lunch...
Sister,
that is fantastic.
...and a whole lot of brunch.
In Oklahoma City...
You make everything
sound good.
...a grill goes gangbusters with
their recipes...
Mmm.
...and their restaurant.
This is Taj Mahal stuff, bro.
Well, thank you.
A Baltimore spot killing it...
And the crowd goes wild!
...with their off-the-hook
a.m. eats.
That's an adult
French toast.
Oh, I like that.
And a funky find
in downtown Los Angeles
dishing out
scratch-made pastries.
You should limit people
to how many of those
they can have.
Familiar faces,
new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple D Nation."
♪♪
So, I'm looking for it,
but it doesn't make any sense.
I mean, like, 10 years ago,
I was here in OKC,
and I went to this place
called Nic's Grill.
Here you go, man.
And I just brought it up,
and it sent me here.
This is Nic's Place.
I'm looking for Nic's Grill.
The onion burger,
the hand-cut curly fries.
Well, I hope
this is his new joint.
This is Nic's Place.
♪♪
MAN: I saw them show it on
"Triple D," and it was great.
Everybody loves going to Nic's.
It's a great place to eat.
And it's not just the food.
It's Nic himself.
Like,
he's just a great guy.
Your name's not even Nic.
Justin Nicholas?
Yes.
NICHOLAS:
They call me Nic as a kid.
When I found Nic's Grill,
there was a house
behind a couple apartments.
You're a landlord, a homeowner,
and a restaurateur,
all within, eh, I want to say
probably about 50 feet.
About like that.
That's about it.
Welcome to Oklahoma City.
Rolling?
-All right, places.
What is this?
I mean, this is a monster.
This is my dream space.
So, this is similar food
to like you were doing
at Nic's Grill?
Same burgers.
I've just added
some lighter fares,
like our goat tacos,
which I really love.
I don't know that I'd go
to Oklahoma City to try tacos,
but because they're your tacos,
I'll give it a shot.
So, give me the rundown.
How do you make these?
I take a whole leg of goat.
We roast it, then shred it.
Then we saute some onions and
garlic and mushrooms.
And then we add some tomato,
wine, and Worcestershire.
We'll add some spices, basil,
some lime,
cinnamon,
and then our goat.
We let it simmer
for about three hours.
We do three tacos
an order.
Mmm.
What you think?
Aren't them good?
Delicious. I mean,
That's really good goat.
I just like the fact that you're
making something like this
and you make it sound
so good.
You make everything
sound good.
Look at me.
I like to eat, brother.
It's kind of sweet, juicy.
Reminds me of a mixture of,
like, pulled pork and brisket.
Just really good flavor.
It pulls apart so easy.
You can definitely
taste the cinnamon.
It's just delicious.
WOMAN: From the tacos
to the burgers,
it's something for everyone.
Still doing the
onion burger here?
Yes, sir.
What are we doing?
Just pattying up
some of my burgers.
It's about a half a pound,
somewhere around there.
You just roll 'em up
and patty it.
I try not
to pack 'em too tight.
No, 'cause you push all the fat
out of 'em when you cook 'em.
-Absolutely.
-And that's it.
Let's go cook these.
-All right.
First, I usually put some onions
and get them sauteing.
-Little butter.
-Lot of butter.
Get 'em grilling
down good.
And put our burgers on.
You threw the ball
of fun on there.
And then
just smash it on there.
This griddle's pretty hot.
The hotter the grill gets,
the grease gets to flying,
and that's what glazes
those buns over
and puts a little extra.
You see the way his eyes
sparkled a little bit
when he started talking
about that.
It scares me.
A mess of onions.
Whoa!
All right.
Let's get this baby off.
And what can I get
with these as a side?
French fries
or mashed potatoes.
Well,
let's do some fries.
Now, who was our guy?
Who was doing the fries?
He's still with you?
Jovon. Oh, absolutely.
He owns part of this baby here.
And he was
a fry-cutting machine.
He cuts 'em up to order.
7,500 pounds a day.
-Is that a normal setup?
-That's a normal setup.
FIERI: Dude, that's huge.
Mmm.
That's great, man.
Look at all that juice
running off that.
Can't beat that.
That's what a burger's
supposed to be.
This is definitely a joint
that I will come back to.
The only thing
is, you just got to get
some more seating,
brother.
That would help,
wouldn't it?
How far away are we
from Nic's Grill?
About 2 miles
straight west.
And it's still cranking along?
We still line them outside.
'Cause of you.
Ah, no.
You were the one, buddy.
All I did was shine
the light on it.
After "Triple D" came through,
it was just a madhouse.
He really had to expand.
So now he has the food truck.
He has Nic's Place here.
This is Taj Mahal stuff, bro.
Well, thank you.
So, what else is on the menu?
One of our lighter options,
chicken salad,
is a pretty popular little item.
This is
a nice little setup, brother.
We make it by roasting off
a chicken that we've seasoned
with salt
and pepper, butter, and garlic.
Once the chicken
is nicely roasted,
we'll pull this all apart,
and we'll make
our chicken salad
by adding red onions
and white onions.
What do I get in here
that's a little sweet?
Got a two or three different
styles of grapes in there.
Pecans and celery.
Some mayonnaise.
And we add a little Cool Whip,
which fluffs it up.
What do you think about that?
It's delicious.
It's a nice take
on a Waldorf salad. It's great.
The Cool Whip made it kind of
have a sweeter taste.
Then you also get kind of
a little bit of a crisp taste,
you know, from the grapes, from
the lettuce.
And the walnuts give
a nice little crunch, also.
WOMAN: Oh, it was so good.
The Cool Whip added, like,
a different sort of cream, but
kept it lighter
than a mayonnaise normally
would.
Really
played well with the grapes.
Served beer in this place,
you'd be open till 2:00.
Oh, yeah.
And there's a full basement
under here, too, dude.
That's where the bar is,
and the lounge.
Wait, wait, wait. There's a bar
and a lounge in the basement?
Yes, sir.
Oh, I got to see that.
♪♪
I love it, man.
Fry-cutting machine
right here.
I hear
you're part of this gig.
I am.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I always like to come back
and see where people are.
It's been almost 10 years now.
Killing it.
When I come back
and I'm not working,
I'm coming down here,
and we're gonna have to talk.
Love to.
After some of that tequila.
That's the good stuff.
FIERI: Now, coming up in
Baltimore, a Southern twist...
I love grits.
...on regional favorites.
That on its own...
Is jammin'.           Is...
[ Laughs ]
So, here I am in the Roland Park
neighborhood
of Baltimore, Maryland,
on Cold Spring Lane.
Well, more fondly known
as Eddie Dopkin Way.
That's because back in the '90s,
Eddie had, like, five rockin'
restaurants in this area.
And the one we visited
back in 2015
is still the talk
of the town.
A funky big breakfast joint
known as Miss Shirley's Cafe.
♪♪
MAN: I caught the episode
with Triple D here.
I loved seeing my hometown
restaurant
get a little shout-out.
I actually was here
when it was filmed.
I was just a blur
in the audience.
I have no problem
giving it a "wowie!"
I was fortunate enough
to meet Eddie before he passed.
And his son David
is definitely carrying
on the family tradition.
FIERI: He's talking about
David Dopkin,
who with his wife, Brandy,
took over when his dad
passed away in 2013.
Your dad started
this whole thing.
He did.
He's really smiling down.
He loved diners, dives.
He would come into work --
There's a "drive-in"
in the center of that.
That's why
we call it "Triple D."
My father would have absolutely
loved to know that Guy
and the team
were visiting Shirley's.
One of his favorite
expressions was "wowie!"
So this guy was the life
of the party.
And this is a wowie.
FIERI: But when it came to the
kitchen, the life of the party
handed the reins to executive
chef Brigette Bledsoe...
So, what are
we gonna make?
[ Hoarsely ] All right,
we're gonna make
a bacon, onion,
and Tabasco jam.
That's easy
for you to say.
Not really, though.
...who sounded like she was
the life of the party.
You drink?
Yes.
[ Laughs ]
Sorry.
Did you drink today?
No.
Oh.
My voice was
completely gone.
Sweet onions.
[ Sizzling ]
I couldn't hear you already.
Now for you to talk
over the onions...
I think she said,
"You're a sweet guy."
[ Laughs ]
Chopped garlic.
-Bacon?
-Bacon.
There we go.
And this all goes
for a crabcake po'boy?
Yes.
Next up?
-Coffee.
-I like where this is going.
Apple-cider vinegar,
maple syrup.
-A little hot sauce.
-Brown sugar,
and a little black pepper.
-Okay.
All of this
is gonna cook down...
For two and a half hours.
Now we're gonna
make the crabcake?
Yes.
A little mayo, eggs.
Mmm.
Worcestershire,
Old Bay, yellow mustard,
kosher salt.
Mix this together.
Okay,
what's going on now?
2 pounds of crab meat.
-Whoa!
-Roasted red peppers,
parsley, crabcake mix.
-Okay.
-This is cracker meal.
This is just enough effort
to combine it.
Yes, that's what I call
a crabcake.
I am in awe.
Three of them will go
in the sandwich.
Okay.
Now we have
our bacon jam.
Plenty of that on there.
-Okay.
-Old Bay remoulade.
♪♪
Oh, he's speechless.
I like that.
No, that's you.
[ Laughter ]
And the crowd goes wild!
Good night, Detroit.
Damn. Baltimore.
[ Cheers and applause ]
We had a good feeling
that Brigette and Guy
would hit it off.
There was a natural chemistry.
That bacon jam --
Don't get me wrong.
That on its own...
Is jammin'.
Is...
[ Laughs ]
I'm still the host
of the show.
This is gonna be served
with our homemade grits.
Grits
and a crabcake po'boy?
Yes.
Me love grits.
No matter whatever else
you order here,
you have to have grits.
These are our Miss Shirley's
stone-ground grits.
We reduced some heavy cream
and whole milk.
I'm gonna add
applewood smoked bacon.
I'm gonna add my grits in
right now.
One of my secret ingredients is
mascarpone cheese.
Just makes it
a little bit cheesier, creamier.
We're gonna let this
cook down about 20 minutes.
I love grits.
Now we're gonna make our
fried green tomatoes
for our Get Your Grits On.
I like to add a little bit
of honey to our buttermilk.
Just makes the tomatoes
a little bit sweeter.
We're gonna pop
our sliced green tomatoes
in our buttermilk-honey mixture.
Then we'll dredge them in our
cornmeal-flour mixture.
Now we're gonna
take it to the fryer.
We're gonna go ahead
and move on to our shrimp.
This is our house-made
blackening spice.
I'm gonna add a little bit
of smoked paprika,
and I'm gonna add a little
more cayenne pepper.
Then we're gonna mix
that all together
and then put these
on the flat top.
These will take two minutes,
three minutes on each side,
and they'll be ready for
service.
We start off with
our corn emulsion.
It's shrimp stock, corn stock,
heavy cream,
roasted corn, chives.
And roux to
thicken it up.
Then we're gonna add
our fried green tomatoes,
three scoops of grits,
and then we're gonna top
those with blackened shrimp.
A little bit of magic spice.
Get Your Grits On
with shrimp.
MAN:
Savory and really creamy.
A good mix
of Southern delights
and then a little bit
of Baltimore City charm.
MAN #2: Blackened shrimp.
Amazing grits.
Fried green tomatoes.
I love it all.
There's no question you got
to come on "Grocery Games."
There is no question.
FIERI: Coming up...
Wowie!
...a "Triple D" star is born.
I just want to see you make that
out of some hot dogs.
But not before
she gets heavy-handed...
[ Clang ]
...with her not-so-basic brunch.
♪♪
Welcome back. We're hanging out
at Miss Shirley's in Baltimore,
and Brigette and I,
we have been having a blast.
That was my first time around
at Miss Shirley's Cafe.
back in 2015.
Look at that.
When guy was here,
we hit it off,
and we just had
such a fun time.
There's no question you got
to come on "Grocery Games."
There is no question.
He took out his cellphone.
He goes, "I'm taking
a picture of you
'cause you're gonna be
on 'Guy's Grocery Games."
I just want to see you make
that out of some hot dogs.
[ Laughs ]
Probably a few months later,
I got the call,
and I was flying out
to Santa Rosa to participate.
And it was amazing.
Wowie!
Good luck, sister.
FIERI:
And since then, Brigette,
along with owners
David and Brandy Dopkin,
have been keeping this place
and the two others around town
running.
May I bring you anything
right now?
It's what David's dad, Eddie,
would have wanted.
I've seen a lot of great places,
and it usually has to come
from a foundation
of someone like your pops.
The fact that you guys
have picked it up and carried it
and continue to do it,
and the fact
that you're crazy also helps.
What are we making next?
We're gonna make a coconut
filling
for our coconut cream
stuffed French toast.
We're gonna start off
with some cream cheese.
We're gonna
add mascarpone cheese.
Mascarpone, okay.
Shredded coconut,
coconut extract.
vanilla extract, honey.
Darling.
Where's this going to go?
We're gonna stuff it
in our challah bread.
Holla!
Then we close it up.
♪♪
[ Clank ]
We're gonna go ahead
and dip it in our mix.
So, how do I eat it?
Oh.
With a fork
and a knife.
♪♪
It's delicious.
It's not overly sweet.
I love the texture
of the coconut.
That's really great.
-Awesome.
-That's an adult French toast.
-Oh, I like that.
DAVID:
Since the episode of "Triple D,"
we just have so many guests
coming in,
and they want to try the coconut
cream stuffed French toast.
But we really try
to encourage our guests
to try different menu items.
I'm having steak
over fried green tomatoes.
I have the crab and fried green
tomatoes eggs Benedict.
I've been eyeing my man's
chicken and waffles over here.
This is our house-made
waffle mix.
We're gonna add some white
cheddar and some green onions.
And this is what makes our
chicken and waffles
stand out from everyone else's.
This is ready to go into
the waffle iron for two minutes.
We're just gonna go ahead
and dredge our chicken
into our flour mixture.
Now we're gonna take it
to the fryer.
We're gonna fry our chicken
so it's GB&D --
golden brown and delicious.
We're ready to plate.
We're gonna start
with our savory waffles
and then the chicken
that we just fried up.
We're gonna garnish with
a little bit more white cheddar.
Our Peppadew jalapeño butter.
And it's a crazy concoction of
butter,
house-made pickled jalepeños,
and Peppadews.
People love it.
And then we're gonna drizzle
with our honey mustard.
Some magic spice.
And here's our chicken
and waffles.
WOMAN: It's just delicious.
There's savory waffles.
Chicken's nice and moist inside.
And you've got this light crunch
with a lot of flavor.
BOY: I really like the chicken
with the jalapeño butter.
It's not that hot, but it gives
the dish a little kick.
MAN:
I love the scratch-made food.
I love the family atmosphere.
I mean, it seems like a party
when you walk in the place.
Give it up one time for Eddie
and give me a little...
"wowie."
-Wowie.
You've got to do it with
a little more enthusiasm.
And I want some hands in it.
Okay, so, give it up for Eddie
and a little...
-Wowie.
-Wowie!
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up, in downtown
Los Angeles...
Questions.
Yes, questions.
...a surprising spot...
I never, never would have
expected that.
...serving up all sorts of sweet
and savory.
You got to come try this.
FIERI: Back in 2009, I was in
a Los Angeles historic area
known as the Nickel.
Now I'm gonna visit
a place that's doing
some diner favorites, but with,
you know, California flair.
It's the kind of place
you can really...find yourself.
And fortunately,
nothing's changed.
Time to check out Nickel Diner.
♪♪
Chilaquiles.
I love coming here, and after
seeing it on "Triple D,"
just maybe you want to come
more.
They take regular food
and put a great twist on it.
They have really created
a space here
that has
brought the neighborhood up.
FIERI: They are Monica May
and Kristen Trattner,
two locals who just wanted
to feed the neighborhood
some good home cooking.
When we first opened,
we were one of the only
restaurants in downtown.
We found this place.
It was an abandoned restaurant.
It looks like
it's from circa 1940.
It is.
I love the ambiance here.
All the quirky little things.
Take a look at this.
What'd you think?
We were making
these extravaganzas
out of meringues.
I'm impressed.
Yeah.
He was there
for a good year.
But meringue doesn't last.
♪♪
I was actually
in that first episode.
It's a great neighborhood spot.
Breakfast and lunch.
Saving room for dessert.
I got to eat, like, a lot
of what
are still my favorites today.
Maple bacon doughnuts.
Maple glazed doughnut
with bacon.
Yes. Question?
Yes, question.
[ Laughs ]
Maple glazed doughnut
with bacon!
Our glaze is
with the confectioners' sugar
and the maple syrup.
Mm-hmm.
The bacon --
just regular, old bacon
that we cooked down
and chopped up.
Mm-hmm.
All right, we're gonna
be able to work with that.
Dip, dip, and then glaze
the whole side of it.
And then
we dip it in the bacon.
And that's it.
Ooh.
That could be dangerous.
You should limit people to
how many of those they can have.
We still go through a lot
on the weekends.
We still get people
who will call up and say,
"I drove two hours
to eat this doughnut,"
but it feels like
everybody's...
Moving on to pop tarts.
Strawberry pop tart.
It's one of our favorites,
one of our most popular.
It's a butter dough
with beautiful strawberry jam
that we make every week.
It's strawberries,
sugar, and lemon juice.
And then we add lemon seeds
and star anise.
And we're gonna
bring this to a boil.
We're gonna put it
in an old-fashioned food mill.
We have to grind it.
Strawberry jam in the center.
Take our tops directly on it.
And then we'll egg-wash it.
We're gonna bake them
for 20 minutes.
We're gonna make the vanilla
glaze. Powdered sugar.
Turn it on. Milk, vanilla.
Beat for about five minutes.
I'm going to take
some of the vanilla glaze.
Gonna go right on the top.
Pink sanding sugar,
freeze-dried strawberries.
I got a strawberry pop tart.
Table eight.
WOMAN:
The pop tart is amazing.
And the strawberry jam
is so good that I end up
dousing the pop tart
with as much jam as possible.
Very warm when it comes out.
Breakfast vibe right there.
It's amazing.
You can have breakfast,
lunch, a snack, whatever.
[ Bell dings ]
WOMAN: Order up.
I saw that come out
of the kitchen,
and I followed it here.
I want to know what it is.
It looks like a mac
and cheese of sorts.
It is, but it's called
Smac and Cheese.
A Smac and Cheese?
And I said, "Oh, no,
you keep your hands
off my mac and cheese."
Oh, what, if I try
to take any of it,
you're gonna smack me?
I'll do more than that.
♪♪
We're going to make the cheese
sauce for our Smac and Cheese.
Butter, flour, milk,
Dijon mustard.
The pepper Jack.
And this gives us
an additional bite.
Mozzarella, Parmesan.
The spice mix.
Got kosher salt,
turmeric, cumin.
So, you get some nice color
out of the turmeric.
Absolutely.
Spice out of the cayenne.
Mmm.
Mexican chili
and guajillo chili.
And it stains your fingers
like nobody's business.
Which is what I always look for
in a good rub.
And we're gonna add
a generous dose of Tabasco,
and that's really
what makes it smack.
[ Whip cracks ]
Put it on our warm macaroni.
We load it into our bowl.
Pepper Jack.
Our roasted tomatoes.
Parmesan, bread crumbs.
Into our broiler
for a couple of minutes.
Look at that. It's hot,
spicy, and lip-smacking good.
Smac and Cheese -- order up.
This Smac and Cheese
is so decadent.
The macaroni, it's a perfect
vessel for serving up
all that gooeyness.
It's great.
Rich,
with the bread crumbs on top.
It just melts in your mouth.
♪♪
I never, never would have
expected that.
Sister,
that is fantastic.
This is not typical diner food.
But this is my diner.
So I get to do
whatever I want.
You got to come try this.
Hey, guys.
We got an order up?
FIERI: But they're not the only
ones you got to check out.
Fried green tomato Benedict.
Awesome.
The country's full
of great people
turning out funky food and
sticking to what they know best.
We'll keep adding to the menu
when we visit more places
right here on "Triple-D Nation."
I don't like
green peppers.
You work
in a breakfast joint.
You don't like
green peppers?!
There's no green peppers
on my menu.
Ohh!
Come on down
and ask for the green peppers.
They're the best here
at Miss Shirley's.
[ Laughter ]
Oh, boy.