At the Fieri house, we always
love cooking up family meals.
But lately, you know
what we've been doing?
We've been getting
some takeout.
-Yeah. "Triple-D"-style.
-Exactly.
But you know what, Hunter?
I thought we'd kind of
bump things up a notch.
How about we reach out to some
of our favorite celebrity chefs
from all over the country,
and we ask them to send us
some of their best dishes
from their restaurants,
and we cook them here?
Who are you thinking?
Oh, I'm telling you --
the biggest and the best.
We've got Alex Guarnaschelli
sending an out-of-the-park
pasta dish from New York City.
That is fantastic.
Fantastic.
Beau MacMillan
from Scottsdale, Arizona,
is shipping out
some crazy Asian shrimp dish
you're gonna love.
It's a texture train
going to Flavortown, bro.
Brooke Williamson's got
a New England-style seafood roll
coming from Southern California.
This right here
is a different level.
There's braised short rib ragu
heading here from G. Garvin
in Atlanta.
Delicious dish.
Lots of big flavor profiles.
And for dessert,
it's the Cake Boss himself,
Buddy Valastro, dishing out
his signature lobster tails.
This makes a croissant
look like a quitter.
-[ Laughs ]
-You guys ready?
This is "Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity-style.
Oh, this is great
'cause I am hungry.
Exactly.
♪♪
What's up,
my brothers and sisters?
-What up, man?
-Hello!
-Hey, what's up?
-Guy, what's up, baby?
Welcome to "Triple-D Takeout,"
the celebrity edition,
a one-hour special.
We've invited some of our
favorite chefs that we've seen
on "Triple-D" or "Triple-G"
or "Supermarket"
or "ToC,"
"Tournament of Champions"...
Here I come, baby.
Boom.
..."Buddy vs. Duff"...
Baker's pride, baby.
They've seen you in every way,
shape, and form.
[ Laughter ]
Ahhh!
G. Garvin, Beau MacMillan,
Alex Guarnaschelli,
Brooke Williamson,
Cake Boss Buddy.
We don't get to come
to your restaurants
because of timing and travel,
so we figured,
how about you send us
one of your favorite dishes,
we'll cook it here,
and Hunter and I get to eat
for free?
That's pretty much
the whole gist of the show.
-Makes sense.
-Yeah.
I don't know if you guys
all know my nephew Jules,
but this is my nephew Jules
right here.
There you go.
Jules is running the camera.
Guy, you're gonna like
my dish the best.
[ Laughter ]
Fire in the hole!
Missile one. Vttt!
As you know, every time
I do something,
there has to be
a bit of competition in it.
Alex,
I'm sorry in advance.
I don't want to
have to beat you,
but I gotta do
what I gotta do.
[ Laughs ]
So there will be for no cash
or prizes, a best dish awarded
in today's "Triple-D Takeout"
celebrity edition.
I'd like to rehearse
just my acceptance speech.
[ Laughter ]
All right.
Who wants to go first?
-I want to go first.
-Buddy, you wanna go first?
Let's start with the dessert,
you know?
-Yes.
-That makes sense.
Buddy, wait a second.
I know for a fact
you cook savory.
Did you send me savory
or send me your dessert?
-I sent you a lobster tail.
-Nice.
A lobster tail is a great way
to kick things off with us
because we love lobster.
Hunter, grab the package.
-Whoa!
-Uh-oh!
Hey, Guy, who sent you
the most packages?
I'm just saying.
What did you send?
All right, so Buddy,
while we're opening,
give me a rundown of what's
going on with the shows.
VALASTRO: We just wrapped up
season 2 of "Buddy vs. Duff."
Hope you're ready, Duff.
-Bring it.
I have a new show airing called
"Big Time Bake."
Ooh!
You rocked it.
Buddy, what is the gift shop
like at your bakery, dude?
And is there anything left?
You sent us
the whole bakery.
Hey, you never know when
you're gonna need
a little extra cake.
Cannoli chip.
So we got
cannoli chip and dip.
You dare to dip that
into cannoli cream.
-What is that?
-Is that cake?
Cake slices.
Yeah!
You cannot win
this dish competition
by being the teacher's pet
and sending an entire bakery.
This is awesome.
Thank you, brother.
So what kind of lobster tail
we got?
New England?
Unbaked, it kind of looks
like a clam shell.
Yeah, look -- the box
you're in there, Guy.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, wait.
Hold on a second.
So it's not a real lobster tail?
It's a dessert!
It's a lobster tail.
It's called
a lobster tail.
I thought we're gonna have,
like,
Lobster Thermidor
or something.
This is what we're making?
That is a flaky,
layered pastry
stuffed with pâte à choux.
And that's gonna expand
and make an empty shell.
Buddy, this is not funny
'cause you know I don't bake.
-Ah, come on!
-This is not funny.
-So put the oven about 350.
-Okay.
Take the raw tails,
put a piece of parchment paper.
I even sent them
parchment paper, Alex.
I'm just saying.
Line them up like this?
Yeah, you got to put
six to nine
on a half a sheet pan.
They're gonna get long.
This is the best vessel
that you'll ever use
to put, like, a piece of
prosciut and mozz in there.
Oh, we're putting prosciutto
and mozzeralla in there?
I'm happy now.
-Forgeddaboutit.
-All right.
Throw those in the oven,
bake them off.
-How long they got to bake?
-30 minutes.
So let me just
get this straight.
You wanted to go first,
and now we got to wait
30 minutes?
Hope you guys got a lot
to talk about.
Should we hop onto someone else
for now while we wait?
Perfect idea.
Who wants to go next?
-I do.
-Guarnaschelli.
ICAG's up next.
-Yay, yay, yay, yay!
-Guarnaschelli! Guarnaschelli!
I asked you to give us
a little rundown
of what's going on at Butter
and how you're doing
and all your projects.
This is the one and only ICAG.
I'm Alex Guarnaschelli.
I'm the chef at Butter
in York City.
I'm an Iron Chef.
I'm a "Chopped" judge.
I think it displays what a good
cook you are, with no argument.
I'm a "Triple-G" champion.
I love it, baby.
-Come on.
And I'm gonna continue my streak
by making the best dish
for you, Guy,
"Triple-D"-style.
♪♪
So, Alex, is that it?
Just one little package?
Oh, my God.
Come on!
You know that this is not enough
Parmesan for the Fieris.
It's one serving.
You only sent
one serving, Alex?
-Hi, Hunter. How are you?
-I'm doing great, Alex.
How are you feeling today,
Hunter? Good?
Congratulations
on your graduation.
Guy, how's your wife?
[ Laughter ]
Take notes, everyone.
Chef, what are we making?
So we're doing a cavatappi pasta
with yellow tomato sauce,
which a little bit sweeter
and low acid,
and spicy lamb sausage.
Super easy.
At my restaurant, Butter,
I have had this dish on the menu
for, I think, 16 years.
Chef, olive oil in the pan,
tomatoes first?
No, shallots, garlic first,
please, with red pepper flakes.
Got it.
One thing that's really
important is cooking
the shallot-garlic base
and not browning it,
but just gently kind of
cooking it in the oil with salt.
No pepper because of
the red pepper flakes.
We don't want to mix peppers
'cause it gets too spicy
and then
it burns your mouth.
-Got it.
-Give me a stir.
Give me some salt, Hunter.
Come on, man.
I'm going for the win here.
While that's working, Chef,
let's start on this lamb.
Okay, so you have
the lamb sausage.
It's ground lamb,
a mixture of different cuts.
Usually I like the shoulder
just 'cause the lamb shoulder
has a lot of taste.
Some cumin seeds
and cayenne.
Little bit of high heat,
browning,
broken up
into little bits.
Boy, Guy,
you have the best technique.
Look at you.
I love it.
Bringing it on.
Boy, she's putting it on there.
Hunter, you've been working out
or what?
You look really jacked.
Hunter looks great.
Can I season the lamb now,
Chef?
-Yeah.
-Paprika.
Cumin seed.
I have some really good
fresh cracked pepper.
Fresh cracked pepper.
Okay, ay-yi-yi-yi.
Nope, not black pepper.
Don't mix the pepper.
GUY:
Okay, a little cayenne.
You just put a lot
of pepper in there.
Just a pinch.
Oh, my God.
Don't dump that in.
Don't do it. Don't do it.
I put the amount of pepper
you put in the container.
Do it!
Do it now!
Killing 'em!
And salt.
All this salt, Chef?
I am exhausted.
Alex, can I dump
the tomatoes?
Please, Hunter.
Just start breaking up
the tomatoes
a little bit, like,
with a spoon,
'cause we're gonna put
your pan
of tomatoes and garlic
and such in the blender.
Okay.
Tomatoes are cooking down,
and I don't want you folks
to go anywhere.
This is all about
"Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
We'll see you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back.
This is "Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
We have our favorite chefs from
around the country --
Alex Guarnaschelli,
Brooke Williamson,
Cake Boss Buddy, G. Garvin,
and the one and only Beau Mac.
So, Buddy,
you sent us lobster tails?
And those guys are gonna bake
for about 30 minutes.
Alex sent us lamb pasta
with these yellow tomatoes.
Explain to me,
where's this dish from, Chef?
GUARNASCHELLI:
So I started out wanting
to make, like, a lasagna
that was kind of, like, punchy
with, like, vinegar
and brightness
with a ton of cheese.
So I put it all together,
and I was like,
"This sauce is really good.
It just doesn't belong
where I put it."
So I tossed it with pasta
for family meal.
I was like,
"I'm not wasting this sauce."
And we were browning lamb,
and I just threw them together.
And people were like,
"This is so good."
Tomatoes are cooking down.
White pepper?
Yeah.
Only a little bit.
Stop, stop.
Oh, my God. Stop.
More pepper, Guy.
More pepper!
Oregano --
all of it, though?
-I think so.
-And a little bit of salt.
-Yes, please.
-Great.
And then you want to
take that
to the food processor
or the blender?
If you have a blender,
I would love it.
And you should have
some rice wine vinegar.
-All the rice wine vinegar?
-Yes, please.
Let's make that bad boy
smooth.
Then put it back
in the sauté pan and get it
reducing a little bit more,
and then we're gonna adjust.
Looks beautiful.
How's my lobster tails,
Guy?
Ahhh!
Rowaahh!
-Yes.
-Oh, I gotta drop that pasta.
This is just
cavatappi pasta.
Cavatappi is "corkscrew"
in Italian.
Hunter,
taste that sauce.
Do you get the vinegar?
Does it need a pinch of sugar?
I mean, if I were there, like,
I'd be big-time fussing
and shooing you away
from the stove,
and now I have to
just kind of like...
I think it could use
a little touch of salt
and black pepper, but...
-More pepper. More pepper.
-Okay. Put it in.
I love the vinegar in that.
Guy, I sent you, like,
a beautiful block of cheese,
and you're grating literally,
like, a tiny cube right now.
What happened
to the cheese?
Well, I'm gonna tell you this.
We kicked things off
with a nice snack.
Oh, my God.
It's like he's grating
the rind.
There's, like, a tablespoon
of cheese.
So Alex sent this
to make pasta with.
That's odd.
Where's the pasta at?
Pasta ready?
Look at this, Hunter.
Just like
you're cooking at home.
I always do that.
Look at those biceps.
What did I tell ya?
Bam! Watch this.
Hunter and his muscles.
I had to save
some pasta water.
I didn't know.
okay.
Okay, you want this
all into the sauce, chef?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Ah...
You're pretty far away.
How about half of it?
'Cause I want it
to be saucy.
Could you just say that
for me one more time?
Saw-see!
I know true Italian dishes
are not saucy,
but this bad boy
is saucy!
Yes! Say it loud.
-There you go.
-Okay, perfect.
Okay, so I need that sauce
to, like, cook that pasta.
-Okay.
-Isn't it so silky, Guy?
Isn't the taste
wonderful?
It's silky and tangy.
Let's get the crispy lamb
on there
drained of excess grease.
Yes!
And then I need a bowl.
And then I want you
to layer it.
Make sure there's sauce.
Make sure there's meat
in there.
-Yeah.
-Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
Hype it up.
Would that be good
stuffed inside
one of Buddy's
lobster tails?
-Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
-Let's just marry the two.
Right now, let's do it.
GUARNASCHELLI: And then work
that cheese in there.
Cheese, cheese, cheese.
I almost can't see it.
It's like it's snowing
in New York.
I love it.
Dig in.
It should be with a spoon,
really, kind of
'cause you got to get
sauce and stuff.
You know what I'm saying?
This is not for the --
for the fork types.
What is that?
An espresso spoon?
It's the world's
smallest spoon.
This is the happiest
I've ever been
and not been eating something
right now, Alex.
You did an amazing job.
I love you both.
I shouldn't be eating
this much right now.
I'm gonna regret it later.
-They look happy.
-I love it.
I want to know
what Hunter thinks.
Hunter?
-He can't talk right now.
He's got a mouthful
of cheese.
Whoo!
Jules gets a bite now.
I didn't say take
the whole plate.
I said get a bite of it.
♪♪
I was expecting
a pasta dish, Alex.
This is about as far
on the end of the spectrum
as I think
I would get from you.
The richness of the lamb
is cut so perfectly
with the acidity
of the tomatoes
and the rice wine vinegar,
the fat from the cheese,
and that little buttering
is that you get from that.
The pasta is a bit
al dente,
which is the way
we like it here.
-Yeah, I agree with that.
-Good amount of black pepper.
[ Laughs ]
The key of cooking the lamb
separate from the sauce --
two different identities,
although they're tossed
together.
You eat that bite of lamb,
it really speaks.
For five feet away,
it looks like mac and cheese
with ground beef.
It does.
But when you get
to the destination,
Greek, Mediterranean,
ICAG attitude,
very simple dish, balance,
phenomenal.
That sauce is just so subtle,
not overpowering.
I mean,
it's just delicious.
-It's fantastic.
-Oh, I'm so glad.
In "Triple-D,"
I call that a destination dish.
That's the kind of dish
that you get to New York,
you go find Butter,
you go have.
That's the kind of dish that
if Alex would send it to you,
and you can make that at home,
you will wow your family.
That is fantastic.
Fantastic.
All right, Hunter,
take a look at these.
Alex, I'm gonna be making
that at home, by the way.
Thank you.
I got to go a little further.
Right, Buddy?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
go more, more, more, more.
A little further. All right.
So that's the game plan.
Back into the oven with these.
Don't go anywhere.
"Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition,
some of my favorites.
Alex just rocked the house.
Buddy's got
lobster tails coming.
And I got to get some water.
See you in a bit.
Oh, my gosh!
That was awesome.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hanging out in the backyard
of the Fieri house.
We've asked some of our
favorite celebrity chefs
from around the country --
Brooke Williams, Beau MacMillan,
the one only G. Garvin,
our buddy Buddy,
and of course,
Alex Guarnaschelli.
There we go.
Give me the eyes. I love it.
Alex went first,
delicious pasta.
Buddy actually went first
because he gave us
these lobster tails.
-He did.
Let's take a look at this,
Hunter.
I thought I was getting
lobster tails lobster tails.
But, of course,
Buddy the Baker --
Buddy, how do these look?
A little bit further?
Just starting to
get brown enough?
Yeah, a little bit more.
A little darker.
All right, so we're we're fresh
baking these lobster tails
that we're gonna pipe
in a little bit with something,
I don't know, 'cause Buddy
sent us 18 boxes of stuff.
My nephew Jules
is running the camera.
And up next,
the one and only,
from down there
in Scottsdale, Arizona,
let's see what our boy
Beau Mac has to say.
What's up, guys?
It's Beau Mac,
the "Triple-G" OG.
GUY:
Beauuuuuu MacMillan!
Now working a little Triple-D."
I'm loving it.
-You ready to go?
-Let's do it, bro.
-Come on.
-All right.
This is Paradise Valley,
Arizona.
My resort's called the Sanctuary
on Camelback Mountain.
This is my home.
This where I cut my teeth.
I run a restaurant out here
called Elements
at the Sanctuary --
Seasonal, minimalistic,
really focused on
farm-fresh American fare
with Asian accents.
I'm psyched to get down here
with "Triple-D."
This is gonna be fun.
-Oh, look at that, Beau.
-Cute little package.
That's nice.
Beau, you had that at Coachella.
Keeping it simple, baby.
Keeping it simple.
Is there a six pack
in there for us?
[ Laughs ]
GUY:
Little recipe with a picture.
What are we making,
Beau Mac?
We're making a little
rock shrimp sticky rice.
Beau, you serve this
at the restaurant?
Yeah, I've got it
on my menu.
It's really popular.
I've served it as
an appetizer in the past.
It's a sticky rice base,
a beautiful
sesame seaweed aioli.
And then what we're gonna do
is we're gonna cook
the rock shrimp two ways.
We're gonna deep fry
and sauté,
and we're just gonna
build this, like,
almost like a casserole.
-That's so cute.
-Oh, you sent cast iron?
I sent them
a cast-iron pan.
That's my little gift.
I would have sent 20
if I'd known Buddy
was gonna step up
like he did.
Like, now I feel
ashamed of myself.
Wait a second.
I'm glad you knew
Jules was gonna be here,
'cause that's just enough
rock shrimp for Jules's portion.
-Yes.
-How do you want to start this?
Let's make the aioli.
So in a sauté pan,
do equal parts of ginger,
garlic, and shallots,
and whatever you do,
we'll add the mayonnaise
in at the end,
and we'll figure it out.
You want to get a little
diced jalapeño in that mix.
Just gonna sweat
that out a bit.
Yep. Oh, yeah.
And soak the seaweed.
So we're just gonna
steep this dry seaweed how?
Just in water.
It's gonna take about five
to six minutes to soften up.
That just adds texture
to the aioli
and a cool little taste.
Got it.
So now you can take
some of that Chinese sausage.
I dice in, like,
little 1/4-inch pieces,
and I flash fry it.
Hunter, if you want to open up
the rock shrimp,
some of that rock shrimp
is gonna be sautéed lightly
in a little butter with half
a bunch of green onions,
and then the remaining half
of that rock shrimp
you just soak in buttermilk,
and we'll just dredge it
in a seasoned flour.
Now time to fry up
the rock shrimp.
-Beautiful.
-All right, Beau.
Am I pickling something?
-Yeah.
The rest of those little
jalapeños and Fresnos
you can pickle in straight
rice wine vinegar.
Okay. What do you want going on
with these cashews, Beau Mac?
Just a quick toast
in a pan, Guy,
and a little crumble,
like you can just smash them.
Good. We haven't used
every pan,
so this will be
rounding out to every pan now.
And there's just
10 more steps to this dish.
[ Laughs ]
If your sautéed ginger,
shallots, and garlic is ready,
you want to deglaze that
with a little bit of soy sauce
and put a splash of mirin
and a splash of
rice wine vinegar in that.
You just want to
deglaze it down,
but have about an ounce
of that liquid left
to fold into the mayo.
How much of this seaweed,
Beau Mac?
You squeeze
a little residual out.
Let's make
about a cup of aioli.
Just put enough in there.
Give it a little texture
and a little body.
Hey, Guy, I hope
you don't mind
but I'm gonna take a bite
of my sandwich over here.
GUY: No, please.
Go right ahead, Buddy.
I'm watching you cook.
I'm hungry over here.
Beau, there's our ratios
that we got in there, buddy.
That's perfect, Guy.
That's perfect.
Beau, this dish
looks delicious.
It has so many ingredients
that we chefs ourselves eat.
This feels like something
I would cook on after service
and eat in the kitchen
with everybody.
Alex, I will be there
when you do, kid.
Just let me know.
I'm ready.
What do you want
first in this?
Rice gets lined up
almost to the top.
Let's take some of that
beautiful buttered rock shrimp
with the green onions
and just make a nice layer
almost to kind of coat
that rice.
Take a little ground
Chinese sausage.
You got that on there, too.
That's beautiful.
And a little bit
of your toasted,
crushed-up cashews.
HUNTER: Crushed-up.
Almost cover
that whole thing of rice
with this thin sheet
of the aioli.
It goes out of the broiler,
and it will bubble
like bubbly love,
hot lava bubbles like
shrimp dynamite, deliciousness.
Hot, bubbly love!
GUY: All right, Beau Mac,
toasted up the mayonnaise here
with the ginger
and the garlic
and a little bit
of the seaweed
and little bit
of jalapeño.
Final steps?
Garnish with that beautiful
fried rock shrimp.
Popcorn shrimp are delicious
in the buttermilk.
Nice.
Put some of your chilies
on there,.
Beau, I can hear
Jules growling
across the way
from me right now.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Fried popcorn shrimp tossing.
-In the mouth.
-This is a pretty big one.
Oh, money.
-Nice job, Jules.
Put maybe a little dash
of that furikake.
There it is.
That's what I'm talking about.
Ooh!
Fantastic dish.
Very simple.
Very petite.
Beau, where are the chopsticks?
Right?
I didn't send chop--
Check Buddy's box.
Hell, you might find
some in there, too.
Found a pair of cowboy boots.
Mmm!
-I don't know, Alex.
-Oh, no.
He might be giving you
a run for your money.
-Oh, man.
-Hunter, you look great.
I knew you were gonna
say that.
Your biceps look great
eating that.
Have you worked out since you
made my dish again, Hunter?
-Ahhh, ha, ha, ha!
-This is sad.
This is what I love
about the way you cook.
Beau Mac is
a ballerina linebacker.
It looks petite and gentle.
And then it just
takes you out.
The rice -- thank goodness
we have a good amount of it
at the bottom
because its flavors
all the way through.
The tender rock shrimp
with the butter
and the green onion --
it's unctuous.
That's what it is.
And then I get to the crispiness
of the sausage, the nuttiness.
But then as soon as you hit
the mayo,
back to unctuous.
The aioli, yeah.
Bam. Bam.
Then you get the fry,
nice, light, and crispy
and the cleaning of the palate
with that Fresno chili.
And then you go back in,
and that's when they get you.
Right.
When it hits your lips
the first time...
It's dangerous.
...it's a texture train
going to Flavortown, bro.
You didn't say that
about my dish.
'Cause yours is already
from Flavortown.
You just came back.
You're a rocket that came back
and picked us up
and took us back to Flavortown.
Nice recovery, buddy.
Now, do you guys
wanna see a magic trick?
Watch this.
I'll hand it over out of screen,
and it will disappear.
-Ta-da!
There goes the lunch bucket.
All right.
-Beau, that was awesome, dude.
-Beau, fantastic dish.
You guys are awesome.
Thanks, Hunter. Thanks, Guy.
-Good job, Beau Mac.
-All right.
Can we -- now that
we've had a chance --
I mean...
oh, my gosh.
-I'm already full.
-Shake it off.
-I got to get some water.
Gonna have to go
for a brief run.
Buddy, we ready to talk
lobster tails?
-I am ready.
-Lobster tails.
Nice and brown, Buddy.
They look good.
Perfect.
Thanks, Guy.
-Let them cool?
-Yeah, let them cool now.
All right, lobster tails
when we come back.
See you in a bit.
-Yeah!
♪♪
Welcome back to
"Triple-D Takeout,"
the celebrity edition
where we've invited
some of our favorite chefs
from around the country.
They've sent us a fantastic care
package of one of their newest
or one of their favorite dishes
at their restaurant.
We've got Brooke Williamson,
Beau MacMillan,
G. Garvin,
Alex Guarnaschelli...
-Hello.
-...our buddy Buddy.
Hey, Guy, I got someone who
wants to come say hello to you.
-Hi.
-Hey there. How are you?
Gosh, you're better
blond than me.
-Looks like fun.
-How are you?
-I'm good. How are you?
-Doing good.
Just eating myself
into the ground,
you know,
one bite at a time.
But you look great.
Nice to see you.
Buddy's walking us through
lobster tails right now.
So if you ever want
to see anybody
that does the piping bag
the wrong way, stay tuned.
That's it.
This is Buddy, Round 2.
[ Ding! Ding! ]
It's like "Groundhog Day."
We're unpackaging again.
What's in here now?
-Didn't we just do this?
-An elf jumps out of here.
You need the cream
to stuff it with.
-Is this it?
-Yeah, that you need, yeah.
Okay. All right.
So I see the lobster tail
reference.
I understand that.
How would that be for a
little sandwich vessel, Guy?
I think your idea of going ahead
and making something savory,
that would be
right up my alley.
Do you warm this up
after you do it,
or it's room temperature?
We serve it
room temperature.
Okay.
And then you put
the cold cream in there,
but it could be served warm
if you did something savory.
Now, tell me, Buddy --
again, I don't know much
about this stuff,
but this looks like
a croissant.
It looks like it has all
the lacquering of a croissant.
We take a dough
that's just flour and water.
We roll it out as thin
as you possibly can.
And then we lather butter,
shortening on top.
I love the word "lather."
I think it might be my favorite
word of the day today.
-Lather the layers...
-I love it.
...and as it bakes,
you get the crispy layers.
-Whoo!
-They basically fry in the oven
because they got
all that butter on them,
and we roll it up.
And two people
have to stretch it.
And then we cut it
into slices.
And then each one is opened
into, like, a --
almost like a cone.
And then when you bake it,
it expands,
and you fill it
with a spoon
with pâte à choux,
a creampuff mix.
Now, if you wanted
to get savory,
you can flavor the choux,
right,
with whatever you want
to get that layer
of herbs or whatever
you want into it.
Now, what do we do?
Do we poke a hole in the bottom?
Yeah. Poke a hole and then
cut the tip of the cream
and fill it up.
I'm not a big sweets guy.
What is it?
What is the filling inside,
though?
Okay, so the filling is
our custard cream
mixed with whipped cream
and a little bit of Irish cream.
Nice.
Did you cut the hole
big enough, Guy?
That's good.
I'm just checking.
-[ Laughs ]
-Left yourself open there.
Is just, like,
a hand-laminated dough?
It's not a laminated dough,
but...
VALASTRO: It's not
a laminated dough, no.
It is a laminated dough,
or it's not a laminated dough?
It's not
a laminated dough.
If you put some
of Alex's dish in it,
it's a "lamb-inated" dough,
baby.
You're ridiculous.
Is that good?
Put some sugar on it.
Put some respect
on that dough, man.
Put some respect on that.
Oh, yeah.
Give one to Jules.
You hear the crunch?
You got the crunch there,
Hunter, right?
Talk about his biceps,
Buddy.
[ Laughs ]
Guy, have you been
working out, too?
Ah, ha, ha!
Buddy,
let me get back to this.
And I really want
to be serious about it.
I'm not a dessert guy,
and everybody knows it.
The mixture that you've made
inside of it is nice and light.
So you got a little bit
of that Irish cream in there,
but it's not
too overpowering.
But really what wins it over
is all the texturing
inside the lobster tail.
I don't care
what you put in this.
This makes a croissant
look like a quitter.
This thing is
a texture junkie.
-Seriously.
-Okay?
Super crunchy and soft.
You open that up and put
prosciut and mozz in there,
it's forgeddaboutit.
"Prosciuts and mozz."
Forgeddaboutit!
See, you guys -- you guys
on the East Coast,
you get prosciut and mozz.
We buy the whole thing
out here.
We get the prosciutto
and the mozzarella.
We have to pay extra for
shipping to get the whole thing.
Fantastic, Buddy.
Thank you.
And what I love about this --
again, just another example,
folks, and Buddy,
you did a great job
with your packaging.
And to think about this --
people are always looking
for special things
that they can do for holidays
and for birthdays,
anniversaries,
and the cake slices or the fact
that they can get this
and they can pipe it
themselves --
all these ways
we've all adapted
in learning our ways
to do delivery and to-go,
this is a shining example.
Fantastic shipping.
Excellent dish.
And I'll tell you something --
this has been three of
the most delicious dishes
we've ever had
on "Triple-D Takeout."
But don't worry,
we got two more rock stars.
Coming up, the "ToC" champ
and my buddy G. Garvin,
who's opened
a new restaurant.
We'll see you a little bit.
Don't go anywhere.
All right, save these 'cause
your brother's gonna want them.
Definitely.
♪♪
GUY:
So, welcome back, everybody.
Hanging out in the backyard
of the Fieri house,
and it's a little
"Triple-D Takeout"
with this special
celebrity cast --
Beau MacMillan, G. Garvin,
Alex Guarnaschelli,
the one and only Cake Boss
himself, Buddy,
and then Brooke Williamson,
the champ is up.
"ToC"!
Give us a little rundown.
Brooke, as we're unloading,
I'm Brooke Williamson,
a Los Angeles-based chef
and restaurateur.
We're here in my restaurant
Playa Provisions,
which is a four-in-one concept.
We have a cafe,
a seafood restaurant,
an ice cream shop,
and a whiskey bar,
all in one space
directly across from the beach.
You might recognize me
from shows such as "Top Chef,"
where I won Season 14,
or "Tournament of Champions,"
where I am the reigning champ.
Oh, my God!
Congratulations!
[ Laughs ]
You know, being the champ,
I know you probably sent me
a replica of your belt.
[ Bell dinging ]
I plan on wearing this
with some of my finest,
most fancy dresses.
I feel like it goes
with everything.
I'm sorry. You're not
getting that belt back.
GUY: I haven't been
to Playa Provisions.
Where is it exactly?
Playa Del Rey,
right across from the ocean.
And that's Playa Provisions
gear that I sent you.
You got a couple of hats
and a couple of t-shirts.
And the great thing is,
is you sent me a "schmedium,"
so when I'm at the pool...
For you and your petite
dancer's figure.
I was gonna say,
that might be for Hunter.
I don't know.
Hunter's been working out,
so I'm not sure
if his biceps will fit.
-Yeah, you know...
-At least Alex says he has.
-[ Laughs ]
-Thank you.
All right, Chef,
give us a little rundown.
Oh! I see some
big old fat lobsters.
I see a little lobster roll
going on.
Is that what we got?
Yeah.
So I was afraid that
you would be a little let down
by the fact that Buddy was
giving you lobster tails,
but they didn't taste
like lobster.
Shots fired!
We're pretty well known
for our lobster roll,
which is a traditional
fold-mayo-style lobster roll.
That's not what
we're doing today.
[ Record scratch ]
We're doing our seafood roll
that's off the secret menu.
I got it.
So, basically, we're doing a
Connecticut-style lobster roll,
but we're mixing in
some Dungeness crab
and some tiger shrimp
in there
and then sort of based
all that seafood
in some lobster butter.
Ooh!
Butter those brioche rolls
with that lobster butter.
I'm so excited right now.
GUY:
I see habanero hot sauce.
I see G-Money dancing.
Where are you getting
the lobster rolls?
The actual rolls are made
by Rockenwagner Bakery.
A good friend of mine,
Hans Rockenwagner, makes those.
And they're the best
in town.
So I bought them fresh,
wrapped them up individually.
They've got lots
of butter in there.
Slather that on your face.
-Beau Mac!
-Butta, baby, butta!
Hey, is this
Beau's segment here?
No, no, no!
I apologize. Oh! Whoa!
-Whoa!
-[ Laughs ]
-"ToC" taking shots?
All right, Chef,
let's get into this.
How are we
starting this off?
So that habanero hot sauce --
that's just a gift for you.
But it's really good
on the lobster roll.
I am so
getting after this.
I sent you a whole lobster,
but you do have some containers
of portioned-out seafood,
so each one of those containers
will fit into one roll.
It's Dungeness crab,
tiger shrimp, and lobster.
It's all been cooked in,
like, a court-bouillon of garlic
and onion
and Old Bay Seasoning.
So those are Meyer lemons.
-Beautiful ones, by the way.
-I grew those
in my front yard,
actually.
-Did you really?
-Yeah.
Chef, how are we gonna
start the dish?
So open up
your lobster butter.
We take the shells
of the lobster
once it's been cleaned with
a little shallot and garlic,
and then we simmer it
in butter,
and then we actually
put it into a blender
and grind it all up and then
stream it through cheesecloth.
So we get all the flavor
out of those shells,
which is where
most of the flavor is.
And that technique right there
of making that lobster butter --
the richness and the depth.
I mean...
Tastes like lobster, right?
Guy, you need to take
that lobster butter
and ship it to Buddy
so he bakes his dough
with that lobster butter,
and there you go -- bam!
The neckerchief
is too tight, Beau.
It's cutting off
the circulation.
[ Laughter ]
Little butter on these, Chef?
On the outside
of the rolls,
like, a decent amount
of butter.
And then you're gonna go ahead
and toast those rolls
and then set them
to the side.
Got it.
So that seafood's
already cooked.
You just literally
want to warm it up.
And I sent you
some minced shallots.
So you're gonna melt
some lobster butter.
You kind of just want to sweat
those shallots a little bit,
and then you're gonna
add your seafood.
Once it's totally
warmed through,
you're gonna put a little
of that Meyer lemon zest
and a squeeze of lemon
into there at the very end.
Hey, Brooke, how do you find out
about the secret menu?
I think the secret menu
might be out.
Yep.
The secret is out
on the secret.
One cup of that was the normal
portion size for a sandwich?
It's about a 5- to 6-ounce
portion
of lobster, shrimp,
and Dungeness crab.
Just so you know, your numbers
might be a little off
because I just did
three of them with with two.
All right.
Is there an upcharge
for extra butta?
-An upcharge?
You got -- you got
chives on top, too?
I was just putting those on.
I wanted to see
if you were watching.
Appreciate you
paying attention here.
Amazing.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
This is just
all seafood and lobster
and not a bunch of mayo fat.
Oh, that looks good.
You got enough butter
on there?
He's walking away.
Wait.
Where are you going, Guy?
Where are you going?
Where is he going?
He's just pacing.
VALASTRO:
He's thinking about it.
♪♪
Yeah, that hot sauce will set it
off with a nice little tang.
Tell me about
the hot sauce.
We pickle onion, garlic,
habaneros
with apple cider vinegar
and sugar,
then add some
cooked carrots.
♪♪
Ah, yeah!
This right here
is a different level.
There's lobster shack,
I'm on the side of road,
and you get it.
And then you're --
I'm over here,
and I'm Brooke Williamson,
And I'm the "ToC" champ,
and this is how we do it.
I just want to say that
if anybody was wondering
on what a perfect lobster roll
looks like --
right there.
Mic drop!
HUNTER: That's how you do
a lobster roll right there.
GUY:
So perfectly cooked seafood
and the fat that you got
in your lobster butter.
That habanero hot sauce
is really kind of the crown
jewel of the whole deal.
The little bit of heat,
the little bit of acid,
and the little bit of sweet
just really complements
the whole thing
and puts it together.
Thank God you sent us
another bottle of that stuff,
because there's definitely
gonna be a fight
at commercial time.
Hey, Brooke, you got to send me
a bottle, too, here.
I mean, that is big.
That is rich.
People are flying in right now.
Can you hear them?
[ Airplane engine roaring ]
I can.
They've all heard
about the lobster roll
at Playa Provisions.
Just as you did in "ToC"
when you competed,
you took simple things
and really executed them
incredibly well,
and it's a rockstar dish.
Fantastic.
-Thank you.
-Well done.
All right, but listen,
Do not be worried, folks.
After we have
a little lobster-roll coma,
we'll come back.
and the one and only my man...
-My man!
...G. Garvin.
See you a bit.
-Go, baby!
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hunter and I just had
a lobster roll that was right
out of the dictionary,
the culinary definition
of lobster roll in Flavortown,
from the West Coast,
ironically enough,
from Chef Brooke,
the "ToC" champ.
This is "Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
We have our favorite chefs
from around the country.
Cake Boss Buddy
made this lobster tail
that puts a croissant
to shame.
I don't know anything
about baking.
We all know that's the truth.
But I do know something
about eating.
And I do know that Jules,
my nephew,
inhaled one over here
in record time.
Jules, you liked it?
[ Ding! ]
Got a thumbs up in the view.
I love it.
We had Alex made
a delicious lamb pasta
with these yellow tomatoes,
a ton --
well, there would have been
a ton of Parmesan cheese,
but that's a whole
'nother story.
Then Beau Mac gives us
this rock shrimp two ways,
and it was a mound done with
this beautiful mayonnaise.
Fantastic.
All right,
but not to be outdone,
this is my brother
from another mother.
If you've ever seen my Buddy
G. Garvin judge on "Triple G,"
you know all the energy,
all the enthusiasm.
My man!
Give it up for G. Garvin.
My man.
You may know me
from "Road Trip"...
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
..."Turn Up the Heat,"
"Underground BBQ Battle."
Always expect the unexpected.
I am the owner and executive
chef of LowCountry Steak,
which is my new restaurant
in Atlanta, Georgia,
in the heart of Midtown.
All of our beef is grass-fed.
We focus on the integrity
of the ingredients.
Everything is from scratch.
This is what I do.
So stick around.
It's going down.
Boom.
G. has a restaurant
at the airport,
so he's able to ship things
very easily.
One of the reasons that we did
this "Triple-D Takeout"
is I wanted to show everyone
that your favorite restaurants
also do a fantastic job
of delivery.
But, Guy, I'll say this quickly
before we get into my dish.
You do a great job,
and I agree with Alex
that Hunter's been
working on a lot.
[ Laughter ]
I think Hunter won today.
I think that's
what just happened.
Hunter!
GARVIN: I wanted to send you
my absolute favorite whiskey,
Ernest Nearest was the slave
that taught Jack Daniels
to make Jack Daniels.
Wow.
So that's an original recipe.
True story.
Delicious.
Thank you, G-Money.
The dish
we're doing today --
it is the short rib ragu
with the penne pasta.
Let's talk about this, G.
Where's this recipe from?
This is the way
my grandma raised me --
on incredible short ribs,
which you and I have actually
cooked together.
-I mean, there you go, G.
-Come on! Come on!
Southern staple.
Take these short ribs,
braise them down in their
own liquid for four hours,
super low, cover and close
for another 45 or so minutes.
And then I do this
penne rigate
with the tomato sauce.
Absolutely love
Italian food.
He's my pisan!
You know, when I started
in the food business,
there was no black chefs,
right?
And what I love
about today is
it doesn't feel like
a bunch of chefs.
It feels like a bunch
of good people
making great food
that speaks to us all, right?
I appreciate
that so much, G.
I'm just happy to be here.
So there's three different
things you're gonna do.
So you want to start the sauce
with the olive oil, garlic,
the onion, the bell pepper,
garlic salt, red chilies.
So you want to get them soft,
okay?
Got it.
In a separate pan,
shred the short ribs
'cause they're already ready.
They're really nice
and tender,
so you want to take them
off the bone.
Okay.
That looks like
a Hunter job.
But, Hunter, don't mix
the short ribs.
Don't mix?
Shred the short rib, then
just put them to the side.
Go ahead and break up
those peeled plum tomatoes.
You want to squeeze them.
Do you want me to crush these
in my hand
like I'm milking the cow?
Exactly.
Let them sauté a bit.
Make a small well.
You're gonna add
a tablespoon of tomato paste.
Got it, Chef. What does Hunter
do with those short ribs?
Gonna sauté them,
super hot pan.
Add a little bit of
the broth.
You're gonna let
that simmer in the sauce.
You got some oregano.
Want to get some oregano
in there.
Then you're gonna add
the red wine.
Now you're gonna add
the tomato puree.
So what I did was I cooked down
the tomatoes,
and I pureed them up.
-Beautiful.
-You're gonna let that simmer.
While those short ribs get hot,
you're gonna cook that pasta.
-Got it. Got it.
-How's those short ribs?
Needs a little soft.
Yeah, hit it with
a little garlic salt.
There you go. Do it.
There, the boy.
Then pull the pasta out,
add the penne.
I want you to add in
the ricotta cheese to the sauce,
add the short rib.
Short ribs, ricotta --
everybody's in the full.
Toss it.
All right. Yeah.
And go ahead and plate it.
Yes! Yes.
And then you're gonna
shave that Parm.
Put a few dollops
of the ricotta over the top.
Top it off
with some fresh basil.
A little of the chiffonade.
You're done.
Gorgeous.
And just so you know,
when you guys all get invited
to LowCountry Steak,
when you order this,
it's not short ribs,
it's "shawt" ribs,
-Ah!
-"Shawt" ribs. I like that.
This dish right here gives me
American-Italian meets
Atlanta...
-Homestyle cooking,
-...a little homestyle cooking,
little red chili flake
on top, which I love.
The beautiful ricotta
cooling it down,
chiffonade of basil,
a beautiful pasta.
Delicious dish,
lots of big flavor profiles.
I think the key to it, though,
really is the short rib
and the amount of short rib
you had us put in there.
But awesome. Listen, guys,
you're great friends.
The dishes were amazing,
super eclectic.
I know that
you got to be tired.
But if you give us
just a couple minutes,
let me speak
with my constituents,
and we are going to determine...
-Oh.
-...who gets best dish.
We'll be right back.
It's been my great honor
to sit with you all.
And I hope that the world
allows us
an opportunity
to break some bread
and have a drink
and show you some love.
Amen, baby. It's great to be
on this with you as well.
It wasn't unanimous.
Jules was the tiebreaker.
But we do have a winner.
-We do.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the winner of
the "Triple-D Takeout"
celebrity edition is...
...winner, winner --
Beau Mac dinner!
-Ah!
-Congratulations, Beau Mac.
I think it has to do
with Jules has a major,
major love affair
when it comes to Asian food.
I got to tell you,
everybody did a fantastic job.
I want to remind everybody
that's watching
all these chefs are prepared
to send this dish to your house.
So you know how to reach them.
Go to their website.
Get in touch.
You guys are awesome.
Thanks for watching
"Triplet-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
We'll see you next week.
Adios.
-You guys are the best.
-Adios!
-Love you guys.
I'm sorry, guys.
I got locked out.
It's all right, Buddy.
You were gonna win,
and then it went out,
so we gave it to Beau.
-Bye, kids.
-You guys were awesome.
-Bye, guys.
-We love you guys.
This right here
I could eat...
I went into a coma.
That's -- put you on the couch
under a blanket.
I ate it nonstop
when I got pregnant.
Let me tell you.
Then I might be pregnant.
[ Laughter ]