Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Ah-ha!
It's a first class ticket
to Flavortown International.
I'm drowning
in my drool.
We've got a credible Indonesian
in Florida...
Makes me
wanna go to Bali.
...a Middle Eastern taste fest
in Oklahoma...
No matter where
you are in OKC,
you've got to come find
this guy.
...and in Portland, Oregon...
That, lights out.
...a funky joint all about
over the top tortas.
That's dynamite
any way you slice it.
That's all right here
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins
& Dives."
♪♪
Now, when you watch
"Guy's Grocery Games,"
a lot of times you'll see
that I bring on chefs
from "Triple D" on to
"Triple G."
Well, this time
things have changed.
You see, I'm bringing a chef
from "Triple G"
and putting him on "Triple D."
Confusing, right? Exactly.
So I'm here in beautiful
Hollywood, Florida,
to check out a joint that's
serving up
some bomb Indonesian cuisine.
This is Krakatoa.
Okay, serve, please.
There are posers,
and then there's the real thing,
and this is the real thing.
-I need lime, please.
The aroma will just pull people
in right off the sidewalk.
It's very unique.
The spice is a punch in your
mouth.
Typically, that doesn't mean,
"Come down here and eat."
GUY: And the one-two punch here
are owners and husbands
John Anthony and Abe Moiz,
who's cooking up knock-out
Indonesian from his childhood.
-Were you a cook in Bali?
-No.
You just cook the food
that you know how to cook.
Yes.
There's so many flavors
coming in all these dishes,
and it's definitely not like
any other kind of Asian.
Serve, please, Singang.
I enjoy the Singang.
If you like seafood,
this is really a great dish.
It's more like a curry,
but with a little bit more zip.
What's the dish
we're gonna make?
-Singang with seafood.
-Okay.
We're gonna make a seasoning
called Bumbu Samawah.
-Called hoo, hoo, hoo, hoo, hoo.
-Bumbu is seasoning.
-Bumbu.
-Garlic first.
Ginger, galangal.
-Galangal? Yes.
-Lemon grass, shallot.
And when I was in "Triple G,"
I didn't find this.
-We have candlenut.
-No, you don't.
Yes, we do.
You have macadamia,
that's why.
Sri Lanka lime leaf.
White pepper, coriander.
-Tumeric?
-Yes.
-Vodka.
-It's a sake.
-That's sake?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-No, water.
-Sounds great.
-Salt, oil.
Indonesian bay leaf. Simmer
that for 30 to 45 minutes.
-Okay, now what are we doing?
-Yellow rice.
Jasmine rice.
-Lemon grass.
Bay leaf.
This is my soul.
-The live leaf?
-Yes.
-Tumeric, coconut milk.
-This is the kuning sauce.
Yellow sauce.
-Very similar to the sauce
we made
-Very similar.
Water, salt.
Cook for about 30 minutes.
-Okay.
-We're gonna make the Singang.
Coconut oil,
the Bumbu Samawah.
The sauce we made?
Sugar, chicken base.
-This is the fresh cod?
-Yes.
Red pepper, onion,
chopped lime leaf.
Turmeric, tamarind, water.
-Kind of poaching the fish now.
Yes. Scallion.
-Cherry tomatoes.
-Yeah.
Thai basil.
-That smells like Thai basil.
The shrimp go
in the last minute?
Yes.
We are going
to do the rice now.
Make it like a krakatoa.
-Oh, this is a volcano.
Yes. Put this for
some green, tomatillas.
This is the lava.
-I love the lava.
It's Indonesian chili sauce.
I think we are ready.
-I'm drowning in my drool.
-That's how we eat it.
I love it.
Outstanding.
The flavors are light
but pronounced.
You get the sweet,
you get the sour,
you get a little bit
of the spice.
You get the fresh seafood.
It's really surprising.
It's delicious.
Makes me wanna go to Bali.
I have two Singang
for you.
Every bite is fragrant,
and it's intense
without being overwhelming.
You say, "Wow, this is not
your typical fish or shrimp."
It's just a different flavor
that is just delicious.
-So how did you find the place?
-I work in downtown Hollywood,
so I know
it's a diamond in the rough.
WOMAN:
It's very close to the beach,
and you're able just
to walk right over
and get an Indonesian experience
-Some more is coming.
Today, I had the Semur Daging,
and it was fantastic.
It's a beef dish with a lot of
different flavors
and vegetables.
-Combine it with the rice,
It's a really nice bite.
What's the next dish?
Semur, like when you want
something like more.
I know, you want
"some more."
We're going to make
red seasoning or Bumbu Merah.
Emeril has "Bam,"
we have Bumbu.
Bumbu.
Chile Arbol, Guajillo.
I know that
one really well.
Galangal.
-Ginger, candlenut, shallot,
garlic, lemon grass,
nutmeg, cumin.
A lot of cumin
in Bali food?
Yeah. Coriander.
This is a very important.
-Tumeric.
-Yes.
-Tamarind paste?
-Lime leaf?
-Lime leaf, water.
Shake it. Salt.
-A little bit of oil.
Gonna cook it off.
-Yes.
With oil and water.
-Next step, Chef.
-We are going to make sambal.
-Everybody knows sambal.
This is your sambal.
-Yes.
Red chilies. We call this
chubby rabbit, small,
but it's...
-How is that again?
-Right there.
Why did you go to Texas
all of a sudden?
-Lemon grass.
-More of the lime leaf.
Oil and of course, water.
[ Whistles ]
Smooth.
Cook it again.
-20, 30 minutes, yeah.
Now it's time to build
the dish.
Add coconut oil,
cardamon, clove.
-Star anise.
-Cinnamon.
Simmer this until you got...
-The fragrance, yeah.
Thin sliced sirloin.
-The red seasoning.
Bumbu Mareh.
-Exactly.
Making sure you didn't
forget.
-Chicken base.
-So much smell.
Coconut milk,
red pepper, onion.
Finally, let me guess,
lemon grass.
Yeah.
-And...
-Indonesian sweet soy sauce.
We call this ketchup.
-That's Indonesian ketchup?
-Let them simmer.
Everybody cooked
right down in there.
I think we are good.
♪♪
Very Thai-esque. So much lemon
grass and the coconut milk.
Love the fresh veggies
in there.
The spice is great,
rustic, flavorful.
It's not every bite is the same.
Kinda like listening to a song.
All of a sudden
you get a lot of bass
and you get a lot of drum,
then you get a lot treble.
I'm in treble right now
because that sambal is hot.
-We have the semur for you.
-It's juicy.
And you get to taste
every nuance of the clove,
the star anise, the cinnamon.
It's just so good.
Gekoc chicken.
There are so many
things to try.
WOMAN: And you want to tell
all your friends about it
so they can come
and experience themselves.
GUY: You're a great ambassador
for your country.
Delicious.
There's to Bali.
Up next in Portland, Oregon...
-Oh, yes.
GUY: Things get real with
major Mexican sandwiches...
This is tortas
gone wild
...stuffed with a creative spin.
-I'd order that every day.
♪♪
I'm here in Portland, Oregon.
I love this town.
Great food town.
Got my nieces up here,
my buddy Pete.
Come up here all the time.
But, you know what, I've never
been up here for Mexican food.
So I hear about this place,
I'm ready to check it out,
and then I find out all
they have on the menu is tortas,
you know, Mexican sandwiches.
And that's the least
likely thing I'd order
at a Mexican restaurant
and everybody says, "Listen,
don't judge a book
by the cover, right, Fieri?"
Exactly. This is Guero,
Number 1 Tortas.
Pollo torta, table nine.
Everything is 100%.
They're always on their game.
You get that kind of symphony
of flavor, you know.
And then you go, "Aw, it's
good."
Masa Y Papa for Alec.
I was like mind blown. I'd never
had anything like this.
GUY: But this is
actually Mexican 2.0
for Megan Sanchez
and Alec Morrison.
They started out
delivering tacos,
but landed on this torta spot
after some
real-deal inspiration.
I go to Mexico and I see
the holy sandwich being served
with all the fresh things
that Mexican food has,
I kind of
lost my mind.
We started making them
and that kind of took off.
And we're like, what if we gave
this all the attention
that we'd be giving a taco?
-Torta Ahogada.
The Ahogada Torta
has the carnitas in it,
which I love.
-Just drenched in red sauce.
It's honestly just to die for.
So let's get into it.
So we're going to make carnitas.
We're gonna start
with pork shoulder,
whole oranges.
Just throw them in.
Thank you so much.
-I'll be here to hold the towel.
Salt, chili powder, bay leaf,
cayenne, Mexican cinnamon.
Lime juice. Cover it
in some water.
How long is
this going to run?
For a couple of hours.
It'll start
to render its own fat
and carmelizing a little bit.
Great.
We're gonna make the chicken --
the drippings,
which we use for our
ahogada sauce.
You use chicken drippings
in ahogada sauce?
No one said this is traditional,
but you're gonna love it.
We've got our tray lined in
banana leaf.
So we've got
some achiote paste here.
-Salt.
-Garlic.
-Black pepper.
Whole habanero.
Fresh lemon and fresh
orange, fresh lime.
-You stand back.
-So go ahead and tell me
how that comes out, Meg.
Over the top
of the chicken.
Lay that over in the oven.
350. How long?
For about an hour.
Once that's finished,
tread it for pollo pibil torta
and save our drippings
for the ahogada torta.
So we're going to do
our spicy tomato sauce.
-What's in that?
-Tomato and Arbol
and the drippings.
Let it simmer.
And then that'll be ready
to go on our torta ahogada.
Okay, Chef.
So now we'll make the slaw
that goes on top.
Slice an onion,
sliced habanero, raw.
-That's not gonna hurt at all.
-Some salt, Mexican oregano.
We like to crush it
with their hands.
Just a little fresh lime juice.
-Flavor jets.
Now we're gonna build
our ahogada torta.
First we toast
our bolillo.
It's nice and light
and fluffy.
Put some of our carnitas
that we made inside.
Top it with our slaw
and cilantro on top.
It's essential
that we cut it.
Here's the moment
we've been waiting for.
This is messy and spicy.
Oh, yes! Good luck.
♪♪
Oh, and the dip.
You're an expert.
♪♪
I gotta get back there
and get changed.
♪♪
There's something about
the spirit of the sandwich.
The slaw with the onions
is so necessary.
I'm so ripping off
the chicken drippings.
It adds a little bit of fat
to that sauce. The spice...
♪♪
Oh, you understand the amount
of personal strength and respect
that I have to give myself
not to eat this other half.
That lights up.
-The ahogada.
-The ahogada is delicious.
I love that they've dumped
the spicy stuff right on top.
The pickled onions
are delicious.
The cilantro is perfect.
I'm from Guadalajara.
So, you know torta ahogada.
I mean, that's like
where it's from.
So tell me,
how authentic is this?
It's really authentic.
But it's also
has a little bit of spin.
GUY: And that spin
is all over the menu.
-Masa Y Papa for Alec.
-The potato and masa?
-Yeah.
-That's a torta?
-Yes.
-Love the Masa Y Papa.
I mean, who would have thought
to put that into a sandwich?
I don't think anybody else is
serving that.
It's really good.
So we'll be back
after these messages.
Get the camera off me.
I want to eat the other
half so bad,
I can't stand myself
right now.
The thing is,
I feel that I can eat it
and I'm gonna be like
Mr. Waddle's comes
down to the...
♪♪
So welcome back.
Yes, I have that sleepy-eye look
that I just got done
having a food coma
from a torta ahogada
from Chef Megan.
Thanks a lot.
We're at Guero Tortas,
a Mexican restaurant
that's all about tortas.
That's right.
You got to be making
a really dynamite real deal,
legit, own it
type of torta
if you're going to say
you just served tortas.
-Pollo Pibil for you.
-Just always so impressed
with everything
that ever comes out of there.
Masa Y Papa for Alec.
Today was the first time
I tried the Masa Y Papa.
It's got that like
potato pancake in there.
You kind of have
to figure it out,
and then once you
do, you're into it.
What torta
are we into now?
-The Masa Y Papa.
-Potato and masa?
-Yeah.
-Oh, so a vegetarian torta.
-Yes.
-Huh.
We're going to start
with some mashed potatoes.
-Some masa harina.
-Salt, oil, and water.
And we're just going to make
a sort of rustic little dough.
I feel like I'm getting a sopa
with potatoes in it.
That's exactly what it's like.
That goes down real lightly.
That was just about right.
Put a chili in.
Roasted jalapeño.
You kind of get
it tucked in there.
Give it another smush.
From here, we hand shape it.
Could you make
this more difficult?
It's a salaried position.
So I'll order this today
ahead of time.
Exactly.
Make sure that somebody
can have this ready to go.
-We're going to par bake it.
-What temp?
-350 for 20 minutes.
-Got it.
And what are we making here?
-Roasted tamarind tomatoes.
Those are going to go
on the sandwich?
Yes.
Tuck our Rosemary in.
This is maybe the least
traditional thing we do here.
Some avocado leaf
that we're putting in,
habanero, garlic, diluted
tamarind paste.
-This is weird.
-Bit of oil,
salt, and some pepper.
-Roast this off at --
375 about an hour
and 20 minutes.
-What are we on to next?
-We're gonna make jalapeño mayo.
Chard chilies, garlic
salt, lime juice, some mayo.
Let's see it.
Okay, Chef.
We're gonna put
our jalapeño mayo on first.
You could
hide behind this thing.
Tortas as big as your head.
That's what we're going for.
That's good. Well, you
almost covered that.
Once our Huaraches
are baked off, hand fry
for about a minute.
Both sides go in and on top.
Wow.
The tamarind tomato.
I think I'm feeling lucky I'm
gonna get three. There you go.
Queso Botanero -- that's like
queso fresco
and it's got a little
chili and cilantro.
Fresh onion with cilantro
and lime, slices of avocado,
shredded cabbage,
and pickled onion.
And that's all she wrote.
♪♪
That might be one of the best
vegetarian Mexican tortas
I've ever had.
Great crunch. It's creamy,
it's spicy, it's tangy.
It's rich.
The acidity of
the pickled onion is a must.
The avocado flies right in.
And you get a little bit of fat
coming in from that cheese.
That's dynamite
anyway you slice it.
I'd order that
every day.
Masa Y Papa.
It really is unique
how they blend so many flavors
with the jalapeños
and the potatoes.
-This is torta's gone wild.
-Posole for Issa.
As soon as you walk in the door,
it's just a wonderful
experience.
It's definitely a local favorite
for sure.
Well done, sister. Well done.
Torta shop. You kidding me?
Coming up, a mom and pop
in War Acres, Oklahoma...
Watch out. When you come down,
he's going to want to feed you
...throw in their Persian
heritage...
It's dynamite.
...into a cultural cornucopia.
That is one of the most
beautiful plates
I've seen on " Triple D"
in a long time.
♪♪
So I remember back in the day
in "Triple D"
before we did the 1,200-plus
locations,
it was all about,
if it's funky, I'll find it.
You know, those little joints
that are in a strip mall
in the middle of nowhere
that are serving outrageous food
that just blows your mind?
Well, I got one for you.
We're here in
an area known as War Acres.
We're about 20 minutes
outside of Oklahoma City.
And this is a joint where
a husband and wife team
are serving up food
that you would have to travel
the world to find.
But don't worry,
they got it right here.
This is Travel by Taste.
Hurry up, Chef.
People, they are hungry.
I have never had anything
like this in Oklahoma.
Falafel bite.
Everything you try is better
than the thing you tried before.
It's just
absolutely wonderful.
This guy's in marketing
or something.
It's like a home away from home.
Authentic, unique, and friendly.
GUY:
That real-deal hospitality comes
from Iranian-born owners
Hoda and Parviz Rezaian.
They're sharing the flavors
they grew up with and then some.
This is Persian restaurant or
Turkish restaurant
or Greek restaurant.
We have different kind of food
from different country.
Everything is great.
You could surprise us with
something different on the menu.
I've never had that before,
but it looks fantastic.
-The samosa?
-Yeah.
I'm body by samosa.
Samosa is ready.
Samosa's is one of my favorite
with the potatoes
and ground beef with a bunch
of different seasoning.
It's very delicious.
What are we
making first?
-I'm feeling for samosa.
-Okay.
Ground beef, onion, salt,
Tumeric, coriander,
and cumin, crushed red pepper,
cilantro.
Potatoes that have been
peeled and diced and cooked.
Is there a sauce
we're going to make with this?
-Oh, yes.
-Oh, yes. There is a sauce.
We're gonna make
a tamarind sauce.
You take that tamarind pod,
and you take the exterior out
and then you have
the tamarind seeds.
That old thing if you
can't pay your bill,
you're gonna
wash the dishes.
You come down here,
you're gonna peel
the tamarind pods.
-Tamarind pods, right.
-I could be here all week.
Boil the tamarind beans for
hour, hour and a half.
-Okay.
-Strain the tamarind
and get the juice
out of it.
And then that's what we use
for the base of the sauce.
Exactly. Cilantro,
some salt.
-Now we make the samosas.
-Couple of these...
-Wonton wrappers.
-Egg wash.
Then you add the meat.
-I'll just have it like that.
-All the way...
-To the corner.
So we keep going layer to layer
to layer to layer.
-That's it.
-And then we put in the fryer.
Let's see it, Chef.
Put them right here.
Take one of these.
I'm gonna -- am I gonna do or
you're gonna do it?
-No, you're gonna do it.
-Just tell me.
Take these
and put some juice in it.
Oh, I wasn't gonna do that.
I was going to take that
and put it on my head
and dance in a circle.
I understand.
Watch out when you come down.
He's going to want to feed you.
♪♪
The filling is great.
It's all the layering
of the dough.
Having the multiple folds
to it gives you a lot of crunch
and the tamarind sauce
is tangy.
Complements the fried,
the meatiness.
It is dynamite. This is of the
better samosa's I've had.
Very good.
Samosa.
MAN: The meat with the cumin and
the coriander,
it's a great combination
of the flavors.
The sauce gives it
that little bit of kick.
I got gyros platter ready.
GUY: Is there a big
international mix in OKC?
Yeah, from German to Italian
to Lebanese to Turkish.
GUY: And lots of those folks
are shopping
at their international market,
which is right next door.
MAN: You're going to
find things there
you're not going to find
in other places.
GUY: Just like the menu.
I love all the different
dishes that they make.
Chicken kebab
is one of my favorite.
I got a chicken kabob with the
barberry rice ready.
To cook it as moist, it's just
definitely work of art.
We're going to make
chicken kebabs.
-Chicken kabobs?
-Okay.
And this is him excited
right now. So just dial it down.
We ground up
the chicken breast.
-Ground onions.
-These are not ground.
These are grated onion.
Garlic, jalapeño pepper,
sweet pepper, salt, fresh mint.
Okay.
-Parsley, liquid saffron.
-Purée it up.
And then we put them
on the skewers.
-All right, Capitan.
-Some meat...
And then we put it
on the open flame.
-That's right.
-And do we serve this
with a sauce or anything?
-We serve it with saffron rice
and barberry garnish on it.
-This is barberry?
-Yeah. Tart, huh?
-Yeah, it's tart.
It's like
cranberries gone wild.
Some butter, barberry, orange
zest, pistachio from Iran.
-Look at that.
-This is saffron, sugar,
and rose water.
-I hate rose water.
If it tastes like old furniture,
I'm going to be upset.
You ready, boss?
-Yes, sir.
Saffron rice with the chicken.
The barberry mix. It's ready.
That is one of the most
beautiful plates
I've seen on "Triple D"
in a long time.
I mean, that is gorgeous.
-Thank you.
♪♪
Delicious. Nice and tender,
lots of flavor.
It's not like a chicken kabob
or a skewered chicken
you've had before.
-No, no.
The rice with the little thing
and the barberry coming through,
you get the essence
of the orange.
I don't even get the rose water.
-That's good.
Very good
for all of us right now.
Great job.
-Thank you.
Chicken kabob.
It's very flavorful.
It's got good texture to it.
You definitely don't see
this much saffron
or barberry anywhere else.
I got blackened chicken dinner.
It's by far
the best meal in Oklahoma City.
MAN:
I was kind of hoping to keep it
a secret for a little bit longer
so we can just
have it to ourselves,
but apparently the cat
is out of the bag.
No matter where you are in OKC,
you got to come find this guy.
This place is outrageous.
Dynamite.
-Thank you.
-Delicious.
So that's it for this road trip.
But don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time on "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
If my family, anybody
finds out I'm here,
I've got to bring food back,
so don't tell anybody.
Don't worry,
we'll be fine with this.
Your mom will never see
the tape. Yeah, right?
Sue, he's going to bring you
some, don't worry.