So when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks --
I got to be --
Can we just, I mean,
please, go to a restaurant
at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea,
how about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner, huh?
I like that idea.
And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love to
send it to us!
There's Roman style pizza
headed our way
from La Piazza in Arizona.
This is gorgeous, man.
A wicked hot burger coming
from our boy Paul in Boston.
I mean,
there's a depth of flavor
throughout the entire thing.
A taste of Trinidad straight
from Pam's kitchen in Seattle.
Bob Barker
would say the spice is right.
And all the way from Hawaii,
my buddy Nakoa is sending us
some true island flavor.
The old famous
"Triple-D" line --
You could put it on a flip flop
without question.
And on top of it all, they're
going to video conference
in to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
My mouth
is watering, man.
Me too! Me too!
This is "Triple-D Takeout,"
and there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course, there's.
♪♪
All right, look at this cast
of characters, Hunter.
So how is everybody?
-Everybody's good, man.
-How are you guys doing?
So we're all the way over
at Umeke's
with Nakoa in Hawaii.
Then we'll bounce over
to Seattle, to Pam's Kitchen.
Then we'll swing all the way
over to see
Justin at La Piazza in Arizona.
And then over to our buddy
Paul in Boston
with The Boston Burger Company.
And this is our son Ryder
right here. He's our cameraman.
Well, guys, thank you
all very much for being here.
This is the most fun potluck
that I ever get to have.
I asked you to send me a dish
that you're super proud of,
and then I'll do the final steps
of the preparation.
Anybody want to go first?
-I'll go.
Boston Burger? You've got to see
what this guy does.
He owns it.
I mean, my girl, Rachael Ray
was there before I was.
She gave you props
about your burgers?
Yes. I got a hug on the show.
You hug?
Don't think
you're getting that for me.
Look at this, if you're going to
go for a big burger
putting mac and cheese on
is pretty gangster.
-Go big or go home.
-Or come here and go home big.
♪♪
Fantastic.
How are things at Boston Burger?
What have you guys been up to?
But we've been going along,
trying to come up with
some new items, I got another
restaurant in the works.
[ Bowls clanging ]
You don't know who Monty Python
is, do you?
I know who Monty Python is.
You know when Monty Python
did this?.
[ Horse whinnies ]
All right. Good, you sent me
the new restaurant!
The chairs are on the way.
Dig deep, there's a sink in
there somewhere.
Is that a Big Papi shirt?
That's -- that's
one of the burgers, right?
We collaborated
with David Ortiz.
So proceeds goes
towards his charity.
I love it.
Okay, so what is this
that we're getting
ready to make?
the wicked hot burger.
"The wicked hot burger.
Wicked good.
Wicked killer.
Wicked awesome.
We had a jalapeno burger
on our menu,
so we want to spruce it up.
So that's why we come up
with the wicked hot.
How do you want us
to start this festival?
The spice rub is for the beef.
We got paprika, a little salt,
pepper, cayenne pepper,
ground mustard, onion powder,
garlic powder;
mix that in
with the beef.
While he does that, want me to
work on the Thousand Island?
-Sure.
-All right, so I've got
chopped onion, relish, salt,
little bit of sugar,
a little white vinegar.
About three quarters
of that ketchup.
-Three quarters.
-I'm not the one
with the accent, I don't know
why everybody's always
on my accent,
I sound fine.
It's not you.
It's us.
Trust me.
-Exactly!
-Now, the mayonnaise?
-Yes.
You can just throw that Thousand
Island in the fridge real quick.
We can start making the
porkasauras barbecue sauce,
The what?!
Porkasauras barbecue sauce.
Did he say
"porkasauras"?
No accent
in there at all.
How are we going to start that?
In a small pot
on the stove,
you're gonna throw in some
ketchup, cider vinegar.
-"Cidah vinegah!"
-Cider vinegar, please.
The rest of the 93 ingredients
you sent me?
Molasses?
-Molasses.
-Brown sugar.
-Cayenne pepper.
-Black pepper.
-Mustard.
Ground jalapeno
and Habaneros.
-Spicy!
-Mix that up
and once it's to a boil lower
that to simmer
for about 15, 20 minutes.
Now we want to make
the hot mess mix.
-What is that?
-Get your Thousand Island back
and we're going to add
in the chopped bacon,
the jalapenos.
-Things are definitely
getting hot around here.
Chopped red onion.
I've never seen this many
ingredients for any burger dish
we've done on this show.
Last but not least,
house pickles.
Yep. Mix that up
with a thousand island.
You should have a kind
of a thick consistency.
Do you have a preferred size
on the burgers?
We do. Eight ounce.
Your burgers are going to cook
when I get those
to medium rare,
toast those buns, get a nice
little golden brown.
Do you make these delicious
addicting,
jalapeno chips,
or do you buy these?
I do buy those.
I don't care who you're buying
them from,
buy that company.
If I could.
Hit it with half
the cheese that I ate?
You can use some of those
pickled jalapenos.
You can throw them right
in the pan
and heat them up a little bit.
Take that bottom bun,
slather a little horseradish
sauce on there,
and some shredded lettuce.
-Good.
Now when the burger's ready,
shove the jalapenos
on top of that burger,
spoon in some of that
hot mess mix
that you made,
Hunter, look around, there's got
to be some raincoats
or something that he sent us,
because we're going
to have to wear.
Now, you want to drizzle over
the porkasauras barbecue sauce.
Yup, just like that.
All right.
Now you can put the crispy
jalapenos on.
-Where are those?
-In your belly.
-You didn't send any.
-Make your burger.
No, I thought I wouldn't eat --
share that one.
No, we're not eating
any of it.
There's no way
you're going to finish all.
I'm going to finish it.
Here we go.
I'm starving.
Me too! Me too!
See how it's dripping
out the back,
that's the way it should be,
that's made right.
They can't even talk right now.
Must be good, Paul.
What do you think of that?
This burger
is balanced,
this burger's got great texture,
you get the spicy jalapeno,
you get the crunchy jalapeno,
what'd you call
the Thousand Island sauce again?
-Hot mess.
-It's named after us.
But the hot mess
is nice and cool
and refreshing and acidic,
cutting the fat which you're
coming to with the burger
and that cheddar cheese.
I mean, just everything is good.
You know what, listen,
I'm gonna go out on a limb.
You should think about
getting in the burger business.
I know...
-That's a great idea.
I mean, there's
a depth of flavor
throughout the entire thing.
Delicious. Now, I want
to remind everybody
there's no cash
or prizes involved,
but one of the four of you is
going to get best dish tonight.
So we'll figure out exactly
who that's going to be.
But I gotta tell you, out of
the gate, Boston Burger,
Paul, you rock the house.
Don't go anywhere, everybody.
Hunter, Rider and myself,
cooking on the back porch
with a little "Triple-D
Takeout," see you in a bit.
Welcome back, "Triple-D Takeout"
here at the Fieri house.
Four of my favorite
"Triple-D" chefs have joined us
and we have somehow figured out
a way to coerce them,
encourage them?
Encourage.
Encourage -- we've encouraged
them to mail us
some of their favorite dishes.
And I got to tell you,
my boy Paul from Boston Burger,
I'm still having a little bit
of a jalapeno attack.
But the thing was,
it wasn't overly spicy.
-No
-But it was dynamite.
And we have our friend Pam from
Pam's Trinidad in Seattle,
my buddy Justin
and La Piazza down in Arizona.
Now we're going to go
all the way out to the island
to my buddy Nakoa.
The first time we met Nakoa
we went and cooked at Umeke's
and had a blast.
Oh, that's -- there's a '66
Corvette convertible,
if you just wrap
that in some ice,
put that out there.
Boom, and that's our
poke bowl.
That's how you roll.
I'm not messing around.
The fish is melting
in your mouth.
I can't get in my face hole
fast enough.
Nice to have you, brother.
-Thank you.
I can only imagine
what you sent me.
That's the pipikaula
for you, man.
Thanks for tuning in, Hunter's
got the rest of the show.
Goodbye.
Guy loves pipikaula,
every time he comes to
the island,
that's his first request.
Give me the rundown,
what's on the menu?
Pulehu beef salad.
How do I say this word again?
Pulehu, which means grilled.
Pulehu -- so we're really going
to take this meat
and it's going to
go on to a salad.
Yeah, you're going to take
that little bottle.
I sent you of Hawaiian
salt and pepper.
All right. So just season it
with the salt pepper. That's it.
In a saute pan.
-Get that pan nice and hot,
want to do a nice sear
on that beef.
Nice mixing in Hunter,
like a pro.
Hunter is doing so good.
Am I pouring oil
in the pan for this?
-Yeah. Just oil.
-You've got a break
on this dish, Guy.
Hawaiian style is easy, brother.
-What else are we doing?
-A Romaine bed.
And then we're going to lay
our cucumbers on the side of it.
We'll top it off with the onions
and tomatoes and a little bit of
that ogo I sent you,
the seaweed that grows
over here in the farm.
-Now, what about the dressing?
-In the islands
we call the dressing
a "bug juice."
-It's called what?
-Bug juice?
We use cockroaches
and grasshopper.
You don't want to know what's
in that one, right?
-What's in this?
-It's actually a two part sauce.
So we actually have a sauce
like a Korean pickling sauce,
which is rice vinegar,
shoyu, sugar.
And then we have
chili water sauce,
which is cider vinegar,
garlic and chili peppers
and then just equal parts
of that two sauces.
That sounds great.
Delicious.
I got the salad, what's
all the rest of this food for.
We got one more dish.
The ahi belly tempura.
See, mine's is simple, but we'll
make two dishes out of it.
You trying to say mine
was difficult?
You just move the goalposts
on us there, Nakoa!
I wanted two chances to win.
We're going to tempura flash fry
this tuna belly?
Mix the tempura mixed
with soda water.
We'll whisk that up real good.
All right. And what temperature
you want this oil at?
350?
-350, yeah.
Was I supposed to save some
of this flour to coat the fish?
-Yeah.
-I'm starving.
-Always getting me sta--
I'm starving.
-Do I have any sauce
or anything
that's going with this?
Yep, you got our sweet
and sour sauce
that'll be the topping after
it's all done.
That doesn't look like
sweet and sour sauce
where I'm from.
-It's the island,
the good pineapples we get over
a better.
Warm that sauce up.
-With the veggies?
That's fine. Red bell peppers,
green bell peppers, red onions
and some pineapple.
-Tuna belly
going into the tempura batter.
Give it a nice little float.
-Yeah.
How's that beef coming, Hunter?
It's looking good.
So I've got the ogo on there.
Fantastic. One more piece
for good measure.
All right.
Before before you toss
the sauce,
sprinkle some of that
Hawaiian salt on the beef first.
Hawaiian salt.
Is that a sea salt?
Yep, Hawaiian rock salt.
Now get that
bug juice all over.
♪♪
-Bro...
-That bug juice makes it.
The bug juice,
the old famous "Triple-D" line,
you could put it on a flip flop
without question.
You get acid, you get sweet,
you get a little funk.
Is there something fermented
in there?
No. Maybe the cockroaches?
No, no.
[ Laughter ]
One of the more simple dishes
that I think
you've ever made for us,
but without question,
over the top in flavor.
Now, do we need any more food,
thank you very little --
how are we going to serve this
tuna belly?
Just make a couple of cuts,
put it on that plate,
grab salad on the side,
and then we're going to
top it off with a veggie mix
with the sauce
and furikake,
good to go.
Oh, man, if this is not
an Umeke's 101 dish,
right here,
I don't know what is.
The fresh tuna belly,
you can't get any better
than tuna bell, man -- all that
fatty oils in that thing?
So good.
Tender, super flavorful,
the sweet and sour sauce --
it's not too tangy
and it's not too sweet.
When you look it up
in Flavortown library,
that's Hawaiian sweet and sour.
Excellent job. Delicious.
Well, I'd love to say
good night to everybody,
and we'll see you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives
Takeout,"
but yet there's two more chefs
that are ready
to bring the pain.
I mean, serve us
some delicious food
and we'll see them
when we get back.
I'm taking a nap.
Seriously.
Make it a long commercial.
We'll be back.
Carry me out?
Hi, guys, my dad and my brother
passed out on the couch
from too much, uh,
too much good food.
You start the show without me.
Oh, welcome back to
"Triple-D Takeout."
Thanks for trying
to cover us, though.
I got to be honest
with you folks,
I just want to take a nap.
So if you guys can just talk
among yourselves
for the next 20 minutes,
that'd be great.
We had a fantastic dish
from Umeke's,
from our good buddy Nakoa,
and Paul kicked things off
with a delicious burger
out of Boston.
We have the crazy man, I don't
know who the guy is
with the beard,
Justin and La Piazza al Forno,
and we have our friend
Pam in Seattle,
from Pam's Trinidad.
Been a long time
since I saw you.
-You came 2009.
-And there was a lot of people
we never had
Trinidadian food before,
couldn't even
pronounce the dishes.
It's called Parlay the Rotary
Paratha -- paratha roti.
In Trinidad it's also called
the buss up shut.
Oh, gosh,
don't start.
So tell me,
what did you send us?
I send you aloo pie.
It's a potato patty.
It's really simple.
It's vegan, vegetarian;
and jerk spicy wings.
Uh-oh.
-What's it say?
-"Bust a lime."
It's a Trinidad snack.
Bust a lime?
Yeah. Like when you go out
with the guys there.
A hang out.
-Look at that.
I thought you could continue
to celebrate
your wife's birthday
with a shot of that.
I appreciate that,
she will love me
drinking some Trinidadian rum.
I didn't know
we could send booze.
You just move
the goalposts again.
ALL: Cheers.
Delicious.
HUNTER: Ooh, that is very nice.
Let's start cooking this.
Are we starting with the wings
first or the pies first?
We can start
with the pies first.
And what is in this mixture
right here?
Cumin, cilantro, garlic,
habaneros, and some salt.
-And cooked potatoes.
-"Aloo" is the Indian word
for potato -- that's what you're
using for the filling.
And what is in the dough, chef?
Flour, salt, Crisco,
baking powder, and sugar.
I'm going to put it
in the center
and fold it over.
-And fold it over, right.
And how much?
As much as
you can fit in there.
And just a little water
to seal them?
Yeah. You can do that,
or you can just do it
with your fingers
and then use the fork.
Use the fork, like,
the fork is with me.
All right.
Into the hot oil.
Yeah.
Hunter and guys,
Trinidad, come on down, folks.
So that's going.
Let's talk about
these jerk wings.
I send you ginger,
garlic and cilantro.
You blend that together.
There's a nice
golden brown on this.
That's it?
-It's deep fried.
It's got to be good.
-Cilantro, ginger, garlic.
-In the bowl.
Now I'm into the dry spices.
I had the paprika,
the rosemary, the allspice.
This is some clove,
red chili flake.
There's some soy sauce there
and some ketchup.
Okay, this mixture now goes
with this mixture.
-Yes.
-Holy moly!
Come on, that is simpler
than the burgers, right?
Wait, wait, wait, you're
throwing me under the bus?!
Pam! Really? I've been
your friend this whole time!
And how long is this
going to marinate, Chef?
No marinating, you just --
straight in the oven.
-Straight in the oven.
-Covered for 10, 15 minutes,
and then uncovered
for the rest of the time.
All right.
So the wings are down.
Let's try these pies --
and the mango chutney
is what's going to go with that.
-Yes.
-Beautiful.
Make it look good.
Where do I get the heat from?
Whoo!
-Habaneros.
-Pam, they're fantastic.
The dough that you make
is so light,
but it's got good chew to it
and a little sweet
coming from that mango chutney.
But this is what you love,
a full vegan,
what do you call it, aloo?
Aloo pie.
You wouldn't miss the meat
at all,
the flavor's intense.
That's on point.
Bob Barker would say
the spice is right,
Okay, please --
Thank you very much.
Okay, so now we have the wings.
We gonna do a sauce with these?
No extra sauce, just
the dripping from that
is what we serve it with.
This is rich,
lots of flavor.
Rider's a sucker for wings.
Breathe, breathe between
the inhaling part.
You know what's great also,
it does have
a little bit of kick,
but it's a lot of
really full flavored spice.
Yeah, good balance.
It doesn't make you feel
like you need a sauce.
Pam, delicious.
All right.
Well, listen,
it's been a fantastic show.
Thanks, everybody,
for tuning in tonight.
We really appreciate having you
and -- what?
We still have Justin!
Oh, Justin.
Yeah. Yeah, I'm just here
for the ride.
Whatever.
-It's my buddy Justin there
in there at La Piazza al Forno,
see you in a bit.
Welcome back,
"Triple-D Takeout,"
we're hanging out
in the backyard and, man,
we are eating today --
eating like kings.
I've invited some of my favorite
"Triple-D" joints
from around the country,
let's have a potluck.
We'll just send the food
to my house and Hunter
and I will cook;
we've had tuna belly all the way
from Hawaii,
burgers from Boston,
fantastic Trinidadian food
from Seattle.
Now it's La Piazza al Forno
-Hit it boys.
We shot
at their crazy pizzeria
and it was his old man
that was stealing the show.
-Hey!
-I mean, that was a party.
This guy is out of bounds,
hysterical.
What do you think
of your son as a chef?
He's the best pizza guy
I know,
but I've been in the business
40 years.
Can I save that, because I don't
think I'll ever hear that ever.
That was quite
a few years ago.
Where is your pops?
-Hello, Guy!
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Laughs ]
Hey!
What's up, wild man?
You really want to hit him with
a little dance or something?
Come on.
[ Laughs ]
Here's the third generation,
Guys.
This is my twin right here.
-What?! Oh, my gosh!
-I sent you a special hat.
-That's awesome.
There's another gift, Guy.
You got to see this one.
Put that next
to your dining room table,
when you eat,
you can look at my dad.
Hey, boss,
it was nice seeing you.
You look great.
-I'll see you soon, all right?
I hope so.
-That's a hard act to follow.
-Tell me what we got.
About three years ago, I learned
about Roman style pizza.
It's very new
to the United States.
I'm the only one in Arizona
doing Roman style pizza.
We opened up a place
called Piazza Romana.
You had our Neapolitan pizza.
The dough is hydrated
about 65 percent.
This is 85 percent
water to flour ratio.
This dough is
a 96-hour fermentation.
So the dough is four days out
before when I make it
to when I can use it.
-Really?!
Yeah. Use your fingertips,
stretch it out,
keep it into a square.
I love where we're going
with this, brother.
Now those pans are from Rome.
You want to put a little bit
of olive oil.
I tried to build a crust
on this at all.
No, no crust.
You've got a talent!
Look at this -- some people take
three or four days
to learn how to do this.
I've messed with a little bit
of dough in my life.
Place that down
in the pan.
Nice job, Dad.
Tell me
what's in the sauce here.
Just crushed
San Marzano tomatoes
with a little bit of sea salt.
That's it.
It's all right.
Looks good, pop it in
the oven, 500 degrees.
Ten to 12 minutes.
My stuff's very simple.
I don't have like 15, 20
ingredients like you guys.
There we go,
another one.
Walk me through
the next steps here.
PIAZZA: Put some fresh mozz.
A little bit of fresh basil.
No, sopressata --
that's the same sopressata
that you sabotaged my pizzas
with last time.
Does that door stay locked
right over there the whole time.
Look at this guy, he's
sabotaging my pies here.
Please save some sopressata
for the pizza, will ya?
Put it in the oven,
I don't think you need the pan,
put it right on the grate.
It'll make it crispier that way.
That looks like
a million bucks.
We're a team!
La Piazza pizzeria family, huh?
Well, wait.
We're not done yet.
We're not?
We're not done with it.
We didn't cut it. Rewind.
-Nobody cut over here!
-Real quick, real quick,
couple little pieces
of fresh basil.
We have Calabrian chili and
honey and olive oil, correct?
That was actually
my wife's idea.
This is gorgeous, man. You want
any of these chilies on there?
What those are called
is peperoncino and filleti.
They melt in your mouth, Guy,
wait till you taste this.
I can't wait to taste it myself.
My mouth is watering, man.
I'm telling you.
Me too! Me too!
♪♪
That's not real.
It's like candy pizza.
You get a little bit of that
crunchy crust on the bottom
like you do
when you get a deep dish pizza.
After that,
it's just pillowy and soft
and the little kiss of the honey
counterbalancing that saltiness
and that heat.
Well, my friend,
your dad is so proud of you.
I got to tell you something,
a bite of pizza like that...
I'm proud of you. Delicious.
Thank you so much.
The four of you crushed it.
Outstanding job.
You've all had such
a profound impact
on the success of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
And now it comes
to the very difficult decision.
Who gets best dish?
You know, it doesn't count
for cash or prizes,
simply just bragging rights.
So hold, please, as I confer
with my, uh, with my team.
Hey, you guys,
we're all winners.
-Of course.
-That pizza does look legit.
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
it was not a unanimous decision,
but we have to go with...
winner, winner...
pizza dinner!
Give it up for Chef Justin.
Well done, my friend.
Delicious.
-Thank you, guys.
You guys have
all been fantastic.
Thank you so much,
we'll find you next week
on "Triple-D Takeout."
Adios.
Justin, hold on a second.
You know that he is not allowed
to play with others.
But I'm gonna dance
for ya.
[ Laughs ]
I'm telling you, I couldn't
even get done with the show.
He's a wild man.
Where do you meet these people?
I don't know where
I meet these people.
[ Laughter ]
That's priceless!