So, when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks...
Dad, can we just,
I mean, please, go to
a restaurant at least one time?
...they start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner? Huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got a funky
rice relleno mash-up
coming from Chino Bandido
in Phoenix.
It's my happy food
breakdance.
My buddy Chris from Scully's
is sending alligator fritters
from Florida.
All thriller and no filler.
I mean, it is dynamite.
We're getting
a crazy Creole meatloaf
from North End Caffe
in Southern California.
I'm telling you,
a flavor bomb.
And Wendy right up the road here
at Russian River Pub
is dropping off
some of her famous wings.
This is just
one big party, right?
And on top of it all, they're
gonna video-conference in
to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
I like the way you think.
Exactly.
This is
"Triple-D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Alright, here we are.
What a cast of characters
on "Triple-D Takeout."
Hanging out with Hunter
and Ryder in the backyard.
-How is everybody?
-Excellent.
Let's see.
We got Chris from Scully's
all the way down Miami,
Eve from Chino Bandido
in Arizona,
Wendy from Russian River Pub
all the way 15 minutes away
over in Forestville.
And now, what's the guy's name?
That's John from North End Caffe
somewhere in Manhattan Beach.
We don't see him much anymore.
We don't.
He looks like
you've been on the beach.
I live at the beach, man.
So, it's "Triple-D Takeout."
I can't make it back
to all my favorite "Triple-D"
joints all the time.
But I figure, why don't we call
for a little takeout?
So what we asked you
to send us
is maybe one of your all-time
favorite that we haven't tried,
maybe something new
that you're working on,
or whatever you were able
to just put in a box, John.
Yep.
It's kind of that way.
Why don't we just jump right
into a little Chino Bandido?
Mexican-Chinese.
My mouth is watering
as I talk about it.
GUY: Look at that.
Cooks over high heat.
Right.
Look what I happen to have,
a random fork.
Getting a little bit
of everybody in there.
Mmm. Dynamite.
You may get some Chinese
fried rice in a burrito.
-Frank called it con-fusion.
-It is con-fusion.
I'll make you an expert
at Chino Bandido.
The combination
is rice and beans
and any two
of these numbers.
Mark your rice. There are white,
jerk-fried, pork-fried,
plain-fried,
and chicken fried.
Frank was a character
beyond characters.
They should have some food
out here pretty quick.
Are you sitting with me?
I'm going to sit with you
for a few minutes!
We lost Frank,
but what a fantastic guy.
Alright, Hunter,
Ryder, grab the box.
You put it all
in this little box?
Yep.
Oh, Hunter.
[ Laughs ]
Those are big-man bibs.
I really appreciate them.
Leave it on. You don't want
to get your shirt all dirty.
It's okay.
I have another shirt.
[ Laughter ]
By the way,
what are we making?
EVE: We're making jerk-fried-
rice-filled chile relleno
and Jade Red Wings.
I'll start with the wings,
and Hunter will do the rice.
How about that?
That's fine.
That rice is cooked. You need
to heat it up just a little bit.
How are we going to start
the wings?
Marinate them
in the egg whites.
Just wake them up
so that they're a little foamy.
That's enough.
Then throw your seasoning in,
the garlic salt and the pepper.
-Fresh garlic?
-No.
You took out
the red sauce ingredients.
I'm sorry.
You didn't tell me.
We just started
unpacking things, Eve.
That's because
it's a guy's mantra.
Do not read the directions.
Listen, let's just drive around
for an hour,
and then we'll ask
where we're going.
That's right.
[ Laughs ]
Wings into the mix.
Okay. Hunter's got the rice,
the chicken, the green onions.
Oyster sauce goes in
after everything is hot.
Okay.
And then start the red sauce.
Got it.
Lot going on here.
Heat the pan,
then throw the oils in.
Chili oil. Sesame. Canola.
Yep.
Ketchup in first,
right into the oil.
You see this? Why?
EVE:
It was forms a glaze.
It's like a ketchup hot tub
in Flavortown.
Ketchup's in with the oil.
What's up?
Garlic in the mixture.
And as soon
as that starts bubbling,
throw the powdered sugar in.
I've made a lot
of Chinese food.
I have never added
powdered sugar into any dish.
But the reason that I asked you
to send me this
is because I want
to have it your way.
It makes a little
nicer glaze.
Where are
the green onions going?
Green onions are going
in the red sauce.
Got it.
So, wings into the cornstarch.
Yep.
This is a different way
of doing wings.
Hunter, take
1 cup of that rice
and throw it in with that cheese
that I put in.
What are going on
with these crackers
that Hunter and I
keep eating?
You want us to take these
and crush them up.
But don't pulverize them.
Okay. Now we'll get into
stuffing the chile relleno.
So, in with the --
Rice filling,
with the cheese.
Then dredge it in the flour,
put it in the egg white,
and pop it into
the cracker crumbles.
You got the pan
with the oil going hot?
Yep.
Plop it in there.
-Okay.
-It's making my mouth water.
I'm really hungry.
Finish off the wings.
Just pour in that sauce.
When you coat it,
then the sauce is all soaked up.
I don't know
that you sent us enough.
Hope the rest of you
took it easy on us.
More?
How'd we do?
-Looks outstanding.
-Beautiful.
It's a very nice shirt.
You don't want to spill on it.
[ Laughter ]
Perfect.
♪ Dun, dun, dun ♪
HUNTER: You hover
over the plate, you know that?
I'm, like, in
a little corner.
Oh, my God. The sauce has got
such great tang.
It's not super hot.
Nice and sweet.
And even though it's so coated
on this wing,
the wing's still crunchy.
Oh, my God.
Dirty?
[ Mumbling indistinctly ]
Up here?
That's why you were supposed
to wear the bib.
Guy, you want
a sip of beer?
Oh, my gosh.
Now, I put the salsa
in there.
Hold the chile relleno
vertically.
Take a bite off the edge.
Pour the salsa inside it.
The only hole
I'm pouring it into is my face.
[ Laughs ]
This, with the rice in it,
with the chicken in it,
with that really nice crust
from the crackers --
Nice and salty
on the outside. Mmm.
♪♪
Part of my breakdance.
It's my happy food breakdance.
Thank you for the aprons.
Thank you for the instruction,
because there was definitely
some things going on here
that were a little bit
different. But dynamite.
This is why Chino Bandido is
in the Flavortown Hall of Fame.
Not to be outdone, though,
three more fantastic chefs
from around the country
sending their greatest dishes
over to the Fieri house.
We'll see you in a little bit
on "Triple-D Takeout."
I'm going to have
the rest of those.
Don't touch that.
Welcome back to
"Triple-D Takeout."
Here in the backyard
at the Fieri house,
I've invited some of my favorite
"Triple-D" O.G. chefs
to send us a fantastic
care package
of one of their newest
or one of their favorite dishes
that I've never tried
at their restaurant.
We've got John
from North End Caffe,
Wendy from
Russian River Pub,
We just had Eve from
Chino Bandido down in Arizona.
Eve, you're crushing it.
So, listen, following Eve
is going to be
very difficult,
but there's one guy I know
that can handle it.
And that's Chris from Scully's
down in Miami.
Potato chip encrusted
mahimahi.
Ah, hot.
That might be some of the best
batter I've ever had on fish.
Now, I met Chris years ago,
and we have had
so many adventures.
He's got
these great airboats.
Hunter's been with me.
Ryder's been with me.
Out in the Everglades,
some amazing times.
Hey, is there an airboat
in here?
[ Chris laughs ]
Oh, dude. Whoa!
I thought it'd be appropriate
'cause we're making the gator.
Look at the size
of that thing.
That probably was about
a 15-foot gator.
[ Whispering ]
Put it in her bed.
Put that in Mom's bed?
Yeah, Ryder.
Why don't we just
not ever come home?
Give us the rundown.
Let's get started on this dish.
I'm making you
some alligator fritters,
almost like crab cakes,
but fritters.
Got it.
I got ground-up gator meat.
Alright. And what part
of the gator is that?
That's tail.
So sauté that up
and season it with
a little salt and pepper?
While that's going on,
we can get the rest
of the ingredients all mixed up.
Okay.
Take the scallions.
You did everything else
for us,
including sending
the gator head,
but we're gonna cut
our own onion.
Exactly.
Next up?
Dijon mustard.
You've got Everglades
seasoning in there.
What is Everglades
seasoning?
You've had it
at the club, Airboat Club.
Whoa!
Oh!
So, I'm tasting
a little cumin,
little garlic, little salt,
little pepper, little parsley.
It's that all-around
seasoning.
But it's seasoning
with a little bit of attitude.
Everglades.
Yeah.
Next up?
Dice up the garlic.
Alright. Garlic's in.
How about that
baking powder?
You want the egg mixed ahead
of time and then dropped in?
Yes. Mix it ahead of time
and add it in.
The garlic butter
I sent you, too.
What's in
the garlic butter?
It's whipped butter,
garlic, shallot,
lemon juice,
white wine, parsley.
That's kind of
one of your go-to's?
Yeah. We use that
in just about everything.
Now hit the flour,
and you want to just go
half of this at a time?
Put it in till you get
to the right texture.
Alright, so, Hunter's got
that gator all cooked up.
Put it in a bowl,
and then put it in a bigger bowl
of ice underneath it
so it chills a little bit
Hunter, go ahead, and let's
get started on this aioli.
Mayo you got there, right?
The dill that's already
been chopped.
Got cayenne pepper
that's in there, too.
All the shallots?
You put the shallots
in the gator?
You want the shallots
Yes.
You know, we're gonna
have a talk with your agent.
We're going to talk.
Yeah, we'll talk
out in the swamp,
and you'll leave me
out there.
[ Laughs ]
Chris, do you want it
broken down into smaller pieces?
Yep.
Alright.
There's enough, Guy.
[ Laughter ]
Then we're going to form it
into little patties.
How many inches, Chris?
2 inches across?
Yeah, about 2 inches across.
You guys ever had gator?
I haven't.
Delicious.
I think we're just about
doubling the size
that these are
supposed to be.
It's an appetizer,
not a dinner.
Well, not here
at the Fieri house today.
It's going full-blown
gator dinner patty.
If you don't mind, I'm just
lemon-zesting a couple.
Go for it.
Oh, those look good, man.
♪♪
What we got here
is a gator cake.
Gator cake.
[ Bell clinking ]
Yeah!
That's pretty
ridiculous.
Sir, may I have some?
Here you go, Eve.
Seriously.
Let me throw this right through
there, just like Willy Wonka.
[ Laughs ]
The gator is tender.
but it's got
a little chew to it.
Little bit of that scallion
in there,
a little bit of the garlic,
a tiny bit of binder,
and all thriller
and no filler.
I mean, it is dynamite.
Hunter just ate two.
-Well done, my friend.
-Thank you, brother.
Nicely done.
And I don't want you folks
to go anywhere.
Coming up, all the way
from Manhattan Beach,
our buddy John
from North End Caffe.
We'll see you in a bit.
♪♪
Welcome back to
"Hunter and Guy Eat the World."
That should be
the name of the show.
It's not the name of the show,
but it's actually "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives Takeout."
And I got to tell you,
so far, we are stuffed.
Yeah.
So, here's the deal.
I've asked all my favorite
chefs, these "Triple-D" O.G.s,
to send me their dishes.
Some drove their dishes
over to us
like Wendy
from Russian River Pub.
And I don't think
the chefs are aware of this.
They are all playing for
the opportunity to be Best Dish.
That's correct.
And as we all know,
Best Dish does not get
any cash or prizes.
No.
Bragging rights.
Nothing.
Just bragging rights alone,
which is enough when you're
hanging out with this group.
The Jade Red Wings
that came out of Chino Bandido
along with the chili relleno
stuffed with fried rice,
the bomb.
And then over from Scully's
down in Miami,
we had these fantastic
gator fritters.
And who's up next?
John from Manhattan Beach,
North End Caffe,
GUY: 20 feet from the beach?
JOHN: About 40.
What a corner spot
of real estate, baby.
It's not bad, bud. It's not bad.
No, it's not bad.
Tiny, little place,
this big.
But this --
[ Imitates whip ]
I didn't mean to hit you.
Why? Why do that?
This much flavor.
We are doing the kalua pig
Monte Cristo egg rolls.
We've got our wasabi mojo
and our teriyaki sauce.
Take a look at that.
I just want
to hear you say "Money."
That's like bank.
Bank?
I mean, there's money,
and then there's bank.
I'm telling you,
a flavor bomb.
Okay. "Flavor -- death
from my own coca leaf tea."
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
That's not --
Okay, that's it.
I quit.
I've never seen you get scared.
That was so worth it.
Well, because it was
down here.
Ryder wants to wear it now.
There you go.
What do we got
here, brother?
"A blade made from a '68 Camaro
spring steel."
Yeah, I made that.
Whoa!
This was handmade, hand-forged?
Yeah.
Thank you.
You packed this nicely.
What's on the menu?
We got some meatloaf.
Slice it as much as you want.
Give me the breakdown
on the meatloaf.
What's in here?
Got a pretty lean ground beef,
85/15.
Then throw in
some diced andouille
that we make, smoke it here.
You make the sausage there?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I like
to make stuff, man.
Celery, bell pepper, onion.
I'll do this.
Hunter's got the slices going.
And when you flip those,
make the slaw.
Slice the cabbage
how you like,
as much onion as you like.
What's going here
for my dressing?
There's the mayo. A little bit
of apple cider vinegar.
You're going to take a pinch
of the salt and sugar mixture,
and then I got the fermented
Fresno chilies.
You can rough-chop those
or slice them.
Where do you want
the green onions going, Chef?
Throw them in the slaw.
Just make that real pretty.
Got it. Got it. Got it.
I make that slaw
a couple of times a day.
The Fresno chilies in that?
Yeah.
I get a little funk
right in the nose.
Nice. That's the idea.
Dynamite.
Just like we used to do
when he was little,
last week.
Choo-choo train.
This is why
I like doing it this way
versus "Triple-D"
at your restaurant,
'cause I can just
pick up the bowl and eat it
'cause we're at my kitchen.
Nice.
Glaze the meatloaf.
Real simple glaze --
just ketchup,
barbecue sauce,
little bit of Worcestershire,
and give it
like 45 seconds.
Slap that cheese on.
Got some nice potato buns
made right here
in Manhattan Beach.
Butter them up,
put them on the flat top.
Alright. Stack that thing.
♪♪
That looks so good.
They're biting in tandem.
Like father, like son.
Teamwork.
GUY: Bro.
When Ryder shows up --
Listen, he's filming
on the other side here.
When he gets his shot in here,
what do you think, buddy?
Who's Daddy's Little Piggy?
Oinky, oinky!
What do you think?
That is some
fantastic meatloaf.
Bro, prime-time example of
the type of food that you make.
I think this deserves
to be called
something like the North End
Bomb Meatloaf Sandwich.
Just call it The Bomb.
This is the best thing you've
ever sent me that I've cooked
that you made
that I cooked...
This is the best meatloaf
sandwich I've ever had.
...that we've ever done.
Meatloaf's got texture.
Dynamite bun, by the way.
The funk of the slaw
carries it
in so many directions.
♪♪
Nice.
That one right there...
Nice job.
...lights out.
Okay. Well, listen, this is
just one big party, right?
We've had alligator. We've had
the Bomb Meatloaf Sandwich.
We've had wings
and a chile relleno.
But, ladies and gentlemen, we're
going to step back into history
to the beginning
of "Triple-D."
We're going to
the Russian River Pub
with my friend Wendy
when we come back.
-Don't go anywhere.
-Way to go, Wendy.
Just one little niblet.
Wow. Look at you.
So, welcome back
to the food coma team.
I'm Guy.
I'm...full.
You're Hunter.
Oh, that's Hunter. That's it.
Hey, listen. This is really
getting out of control.
We start out
with Chino Bandido.
Then we head over
to Scully's in Miami.
Then we hit
Manhattan Beach,
where our buddy John
made us a meatloaf sandwich.
I don't know
if I can take any more,
but I do know who's coming up.
She's more O.G.
than probably anybody you'll
ever meet on "Triple-D."
We've been to
over 1,300 locations.
And my friend Wendy
at the Russian River Pub,
she was the sixth one.
We were shooting the pilot
for "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
I said, "Listen, we got to go
to one of my places."
And we go to our
favorite wing spot,
which was like
25 minutes away
at a little town
called Forestville.
♪♪
Ain't no thing
but a chicken wing.
I want everything
that comes out of my kitchen --
I want to be proud of it.
This is eyeball recipe?
No, we got it down.
Everybody has
a good eyeball.
Some people have two.
Two.
And Brenda's still with you,
correct?
She is, yeah.
You have got a lot of flavors
going on in a little spot.
I think I could put this
on a flip-flop,
it would taste good.
She's the best.
Tell her I said hi.
I will.
So, Wendy delivered this
in her really cool truck.
Nice.
Supporting local artists.
I know you love to skate.
Is that really a local artist?
A local artist, yes.
That is awesome. Wen.
Thank you.
-You're awesome.
-You're the best.
Give me a rundown
of what we're making.
We're going to do
wings in barbecue sauce,
as well as
the homemade blue cheese.
Are the wings raw,
or are they --
They're par-cooked,
so they'll need to cook
about 12 minutes.
Alright.
While Hunter starts the wings,
walk me through
the blue cheese.
In a mixing bowl,
put in the mayo.
Hunter's making noise over here
with his friend the fryer.
Then the seasoning.
Onion, pepper, salt, garlic.
And a little bit of lemon juice,
maybe 2 tablespoons.
Fantastic.
And then the blue cheese
crumbles marked "first."
Okay.
You're just going to go ahead
and use a wand mixer.
Like, an immersion blender?
Yes.
You're getting
the old-fashioned one.
Okay. When in Rome.
When in Rome.
Exactly.
So, just breaking it down
so we get the blue cheese
broken down into smaller pieces
so it works its flavor
into the mayonnaise, correct?
Correct.
Okay.
Fold in the remaining
blue cheese crumbles.
Got it now.
This blue cheese is intended
to be the chunky factor.
Your flavor burst.
Flavor burst.
That's actually
a real word.
Is it?
Yeah.
What's up next, Wen?
The homemade barbecue sauce.
Okay, great.
Typically, I would put that
in kind of a little bit
of a bigger pot
as opposed to a pan.
Now I got to take down
my display.
There we go.
Okay. First up?
You can do the beer first.
That works.
Apple cider.
Put in the molasses.
Chopped yellow onions.
Onion right here.
Fresh minced garlic.
No flavor
in this one, Wen.
And then Worcestershire.
1 tablespoon
of the salt and pepper mix.
The sriracha sauce,
the Dijon, liquid smoke.
And the creamy hot
horseradish.
Reduce this down, and then
you add in the brown sugar
and the ketchup.
And then,
how are your wings doing?
Are those ready for --
Wings are great.
They're coming out.
Okay, great.
Then you just want to let
a little bit
of the oil come off.
So let's drop a couple of the
wings into the barbecue sauce.
Dirty'd be losing
his mind right now.
Yeah. Our buddy Paul Thompson,
who's a big Russian River fan,
would be out of his mind
right now.
We should actually call him,
tease him.
Here you go.
Right.
We have Russian River Pub wings
that Wendy sent us.
We just wanted to let you know
that you're not having them.
Paul: Aw, man.
Oh, those are good.
He's so sad!
Here, go in
for the bite, Paul.
[ Laughter ]
Alright, brother.
We'll see you soon.
That was worth everything
of my whole day.
That was great.
I'm telling you what,
the blue cheese
tastes like
real blue cheese.
It's the method
in which you do it.
You mix that blue cheese
into the mayo
and then you throw
those crumbles in the last bit
so you don't lose them.
The wings are straightforward.
I like that you put
a little pre-cook on them
so they get nice and crispy.
That barbecue sauce,
you get that beer in there?
Ah, it's the best.
Let's be serious, folks.
I got to tell you something.
You're all great friends,
and you've done a fantastic job.
And now you are the O.G.s.
So thank you very much.
You've been awesome today.
-Yeah!
-Thank you so much.
And to not say goodbye
without making the award,
I got to confer
with my two co-hosts
on who's getting Best Dish.
John, I think you got this
maybe. I don't know.
Your blue cheese
would be really good
on the meatloaf sandwich, too.
-Yeah, it would.
-Oh, okay!
A collaborative effort.
I like it.
Ladies and gentlemen,
drum roll, please.
Best Dish, no cash, no prizes,
goes to...
our brother John
at North End Caffe!
-Congratulations.
-Yay!
You get all
the bragging rights, buddy.
Everything was delicious.
Love you guys.
-See you next week.
-Thank you.
-"Triple-D Takeout."
-Love you.
Adiós.
[ Laughs ]
That's not --
Okay, that's it.
I quit.
I have never seen --
Oh, God!
JOHN: Yeah, a little Manhattan
Beach Mardi Gras for you, boy.
No, that wasn't no
Mardi Gras nothing.
That's evil clown stuff
right there.