So, when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks...
Dad, can we just,
I mean, please, go to
a restaurant at least one time?
...they start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner? Huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We got crazy Giovanni
sending his real-deal Italian
from Scottsdale.
It makes you feel good.
GUY: Suzi from Trina's
Starlite Lounge near Boston
is sending some chorizo
and octopus croquetas.
Ta-da!
We've got Ben from
one of my favorite
American-Indian restaurants,
Tocabe,
shipping us a rabbit tostada.
This is, like,
next level.
And my blond brother
from another mother Glenn
is sending short ribs
all the way from his joint
in a Hawaiian bowling alley.
I mean, they're short ribs
this big, you guys.
I mean, they're monsters.
And on top of it all, they're
gonna video-conference in
to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
I like the way you think.
Exactly.
This is
"Triple-D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Welcome, everybody.
Nice to see you.
-How's it going?
-Welcome to "Triple-D Takeout."
I've got my son Hunter,
my nephew Jules,
and running the camera over
there, the effervescent Ryder.
Say hi, Ryder.
-Hello.
All right. So we have Suzi
from Trina's Starlite Lounge.
We have our good buddy Glenn
from the Alley Restaurant at --
and I get it wrong
every time --
Aiea Bowl.
I get it right? Close enough?
-Right.
Glenn,
what is in the background there?
Is that a "Guy Fieri
for president" --
-Yes.
-That's great.
-Right in the bowling alley?
-That's for you, Guy.
We've got Ben from Tocabe,
and we've got
the one and only Giovanni
from Andreoli Italian Grocer.
All right. So you guys know
the game plan. Here it is.
I call up some of my favorite
chefs from around the country,
and I say, "Hey, would you
be interested in packaging up
one of your favorite new dishes
that I haven't tried yet
and sending it to us
here at the Fieri house?"
Because we're hungry.
-We're hungry.
GUY: And we'll finish
the preparation for you.
Who wants to go first?
-Me!
Suz,
Trina's Starlite Lounge.
Competed on "Triple G,"
a dynamite chef.
What a fantastic visit.
When I drove up here,
some person yelled to me
from your neighborhood
that said, "You're gonna have
the chicken and waffles."
[ Laughing ] Did they really?
That's awesome.
That's good fried chicken
like your mom would make.
Got it going on, girl.
Three boxes today.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Like, it was going all the way
across country. I was scared.
Oh, is this your new place?
Paddle Inn?
Yeah, that's the one
we opened up
in Newburyport, Massachusetts,
where it's North Shore.
-North Shore.
-Close to Italy.
Yes, exactly.
GUY: What exactly
are we making?
We're gonna make
croquetas de polpo today.
It's octopus
and potato croquettes.
Do we see octopus, guys?
They have tentacles.
They look creepy.
[ Laughs ]
The one that says "octopus"
on it, probably.
Oh, you mean
this octopus?
So we braise it in red wine,
onion, celery, carrot.
About two hours
on super-low heat.
And then we strain it,
clean it,
and then we pack it
in olive oil and oregano.
Pull them out
and drain them a little bit.
We're gonna heat them up
with the chorizo
to make a pan sauce.
-Got it.
So Jules is working on that.
What do you want us to do next?
-The romesco sauce.
-Okay.
Roasted red bell peppers.
-In the pan.
-Tomatoes.
-The almonds and the garlic.
Cook that until it's about
half reduced.
While we're doing that,
mix the croquetas together.
You should have potatoes.
-Okay.
-That Gouda you're eating.
-What Gouda?
This Gouda?
-Yeah, that Gouda.
That's not my Gouda.
Cooked russets.
Gouda goes in it.
Couple more pieces
in mouth, yep.
Cooked chorizo, aioli,
whole-grain mustard, and chives.
Chive turkey.
Hunter wants to smash these.
Yeah. You're basically
making mashed potatoes.
Tell me about
the octopus sauce.
Put a little bit of oil.
-Fresh chorizo.
-Put the octopus now
on the other side
of that pan.
-Octopus right here.
-Yeah.
Hunter is ready
to start rolling the croquetas.
We're gonna make
a flour dredge.
Yeah, so the garlic powder
and the paprika go in the panko.
I'm running out of bowls.
Can I put the garlic
into the octopus sauce yet?
Yeah, sorry. The garlic should
be in the octopus sauce.
Put the tomatoes in,
and we're gonna blister those.
-You put Guy to the test, man.
-[ Laughing ] I know.
-What size do you
want these, Suz?
-A good handful.
Make it in a ball
and then flatten it a little bit
so the inside gets really hot
when you fry it.
-You want something like that?
-Absolutely.
Flour, buttermilk, flour,
buttermilk, then panko.
All right. Welcome to the
96-item cooking hour. I'm Guy.
The tomatoes are blistered.
Throw your cipollinis
and your olives in there.
Beautiful-looking sauce,
by the way, Chef.
White wine now down.
-And then we're gonna
melt with the butter
and finish with the parsley.
-Excellent. Romesco is reduced
down by about half.
-Great.
-Go to the food
processor with that?
-Yes, please.
And you're just gonna
pulse it, Jules.
We want it
to be a little rustic.
Did we get the sambal
in that romesco?
Yes, we did.
Perfect. You're doing
really good, Hunter.
Thank you. How long do these
take to cook?
They're about
four to five minutes.
You want them golden brown.
All right.
So let's talk about this salad
that's gonna go along
with this.
So the perfectly-shaved
asparagus and celery in.
Parsley, celery leaf.
Nice move.
A little touch of salt.
And this bloomed orange oil
that you already did.
Yeah, perfect.
If you don't mind, I'm putting
a little black pepper.
Beautiful salad.
How do we want to plate this up?
Make a gorgeous round circle
of the romesco sauce.
Beautiful.
Take one of these.
They're screaming hot.
Drop it right in the center.
The octopus next.
-Right on top.
-Gorgeous!
SUZI:
And now we're gonna put salad
right on top.
Ta-da!
Huh?
-I'm jealous.
That looks delicious.
♪♪
-Oh!
-That baby octopus is so tender.
-Mmm!
-And what you really
need to make sure
is get the bite
with the romesco.
Everything
is in balance.
-Mmm, mmm, mmm, mmm, mmm, mmm.
-Briny, salty, tangy, cheesy,
creamy, crunchy.
And then on top of it,
bright, fresh celery
and asparagus salad.
-Mmm, mmm.
I just have to tell
my three brothers,
you understand that
for no cash or prizes,
but someone gets awarded
Best Dish.
This is how we open the show?
-Now I'm concerned.
Everybody's got problems,
except for you at home
who's watching the show.
You got no problem because
all you got to do is come back
and see our next three chefs
on "Triple-D Takeout."
Can we make our own plate of
this, or are we all sharing?
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple-D Takeout."
Our friend Suzi from
Trina's Starlite Lounge
sent us a croqueta
with octopus.
It was a feast.
-It was a feast.
This is Hunter,
my nephew Jules.
We have our buddy Glenn
from the Alley Restaurant
at Aiea Bowl,
Giovanni from
Andreoli Italian Grocer.
Now, this place coming up is
a Triple-D OG of another level.
This is the first
American-Indian restaurant
that we ever did.
It was beyond just the food.
It was the cultural experience.
It was seeing
these young entrepreneurs
really embracing
their heritage.
We're all still huge fans.
This is Tocabe.
-Chicken Indian taco.
Some green chilies, onions.
-Enough already.
Tomatoes. Make it look real
pretty with with sour cream.
The fry bread is the bomb.
I mean, completely off-the-hook.
Hominy salsa.
You're gonna mess up the way
people look at a taco. Mmm!
What are
we getting into?
We're gonna do
a braised rabbit
with Indian corn tostada.
Those are some gifts
from me right there.
That's actually our olive oil we
use from the Yocha Dehe tribe,
which is right over the hill
from you in Yolo County.
GUY: I know that you're always
trying to source
American-Indian producers.
That's what's awesome
about this dish.
Bunch of our native
food producers in there.
That's your rabbit stock
right there.
So we got you
a fully-cooked rabbit.
We try and layer flavors,
so on that rabbit,
you have powdered sweet corn,
you've got juniper, sumac.
That sumac gives that
little lemony sweetness.
How was the rabbit braised?
We actually make
a traditional Osage corn soup.
So we take that corn stock,
roasted the Mexican red chilies,
sage leaves,
charred onions,
and then do a five-hour braise
on that.
How big was the rabbit,
you said?
Seven pounds.
Get that rabbit in that stock.
It's ready to rock.
You just got to
get it hot.
-What are the name of these?
-Teparies.
They're a desert bean.
That's why they're so small.
Man, flavor's awesome.
So you have some
fully-cooked beans
that haven't been
sautéed down yet.
Little olive oil.
Shallots first?
Yep. A little salt
and pepper on those.
Once those
are translucent,
then you're just gonna throw in
your teparies.
We're gonna cook
those through.
Is there a bag of dried
red chilies over there?
-Yeah.
-Throw a couple of those in
with that rabbit stock.
-Okay.
-Those are New Mexican
red chilies.
-All right. Beans could go in
with the shallots now?
-Yep.
Render those down a little bit.
We're gonna pulse those
and then make kind of
a chunky refried bean almost.
-Got it.
What is this little packet
of sauce you gave me?
That's maple syrup. That's also
a native-produced product,
as well.
And that's gonna go
in our vinaigrette
for the butternut squash.
-Take it, Hunter.
-There should be
some olive oil there.
White wine vinegar.
Get that mustard in.
There should be
a sweet corn powder.
What makes it sweet?
Is there sugar added to it?
No, no, no.
That's just the natural corn.
I mean, it tastes like there's
granules of sugar in it.
Right? It's delicious.
And then that maple syrup.
HUNTER: All right.
Cook off
those tortillas.
They're made with
Ute Mountain Indian corn.
Looks like this rabbit
has come up to temp.
Pull it, and then we
throw it right back
in that braising liquid.
Rehydrate real quick
before you plate it.
Here's the little trick --
Take the pickled peppers
in that jar
and add a little of that
pickling liquid back
to the stock.
That's where you're gonna get
your acidity from.
-How is it?
-That's pretty good, huh?
Like chicken.
Dressing into
the butternut squash?
-Yep.
Little salt and pepper.
Little salt pepper
on these tostadas?
Yep. Then we're gonna do
our beans next.
Next is that rabbit,
so just a little bit
of salt on those.
Now you're gonna do
your pickled peppers.
What kind of peppers were
in the pickled peppers?
Poblano, pueblo, green chili,
and red bell for color.
The pickling liquid's
toasted cumin seed,
some arbol chilies in there
for heat,
and spicebush berries.
It's like
an American allspice.
You got your roasted green chili
sage right there.
Ooh!
What about that green sage oil?
Where did it come from?
We roast green chilies
and then fresh sage leaves
and just blanch that.
Oil, salt, pepper,
and then just puree it all down,
and that's it.
Mix the amaranth now
with the butternut squash.
-Look how beautiful that is.
-There you go.
-Amazing.
-That's a beautiful dish.
-It really is.
-All right.
Wow.
-The raw butternut squash salad
is, like, game changer.
-With the pickled peppers.
That little acidic side of that
with that little crunch.
[ Whistles ]
-Appreciate it.
This is taking
what's fresh, most importantly,
what's sourced
from American-Indians.
-Yeah.
-Bro, I don't care if you had
every single ingredient
available to you
that you ever wanted.
Coming up with something
this creative and this flavorful
would be difficult to do.
I mean,
this is really chef'd.
You do not see
enough rabbit on menus,
and you definitely don't see it
presented this way.
This is, like,
next level.
Yeah, it took me about 20
seconds to finish mine, so...
I didn't do it in 20 seconds,
but I did eat the whole thing.
Suzi and Ben -- boom --
knocked it out of the park.
But I know the next two
characters that are coming,
and, boys,
we are in for it.
Don't go anywhere.
"Triple-D Takeout"
at the Fieri's house.
We'll see you in a bit.
This next guy is just
gonna crush you, I promise.
-I knew he was insane.
-All right, we'll be back.
♪♪
Welcome back to
"Triple-D Takeout."
Hanging out here
at the Fieri house.
Oh, my gosh! Tocabe,
we had Trina's Starlite Lounge.
Now I'm --
Giovanni, what happened?
Is that me pointing at me?
That's right. Yeah.
This is my buddy Giovanni
from Andreoli Italian Grocer,
and he is as wild
as he's acting right now.
[ Singing in Italian ]
♪♪
I've just officially
lost the show.
-Our onions sticked
with the cloves.
-Cloves.
I know. Grazie.
I think we smell everything
in this.
-Carrots.
-No, I'm not smelling
the carrots.
Hey, be careful
with that box.
"Fra-gee-lay" --
must be Italian.
-Fragile.
This is a gigantic pizza
he put in here.
Very big pizza.
[ Laughs ]
Dun-dun-dun!
Not bad, huh?
"Fear not,
citizens of Flavortown."
Thank you. Who's Nick?
Nick Radachi?
Well, Nick, I know
you're watching this, buddy.
Well done, brother.
That's going in my office.
Okay, boss, it looks like you
sent the entire grocery store.
What are we making?
-Okay, we're making...
Oh, that's what I thought,
too.
[ Laughs ]
-Chef, do you want us
to pound the pork?
-Yes.
If you want it more tender,
more easy to eat.
When you put in the pan,
you go like this --
one, two, three, four,
take it out.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, that's good.
That's good.
This oil's getting hot.
-Got you.
-Just make sure you take
the flour out, like this.
[ Whistles ]
-I love the sound effects.
That's actually
how I teach my chefs.
You do a "brr,"
you blend it up.
How do you want us to warm
the potatoes, in the oven?
Yes.
You just want the garlic
thinly sliced?
I already smashed it.
How do you
say the fennel?
Finocchio.
Not Pinocchio with a "P."
With "F."
I didn't say "Pinocchio."
Okay.
How do you want
the fennel cut?
Like half-inch.
Perfecto.
Okay, the Asiago
nice and heavy?
That's right.
Good, good, good.
Into the wood-fired oven,
right?
Parmigiano.
The best.
Potatoes and the finocchio
in the wood-fired oven.
Yeah.
The pork out the pan.
[ Whistles ]
Okay, that's good.
[ Laughs ]
Now the garlic
goes inside there.
We need to cook the sauce.
The oregano...
-Smell that.
-Just smell it.
Ohh!
You go get oregano, and you
crack open a jar of it
that you buy
at the grocery store,
and then you smell this.
-Oh, night and day.
How much oregano, Chef?
[ Laughter ]
This smells delicious.
GIOVANNI: You can start to put
the potatoes in the dish.
Okay.
Then on the other side,
you can put the fennel.
Leave space for the pork.
You'd think I work at Andreoli's
the way I do this now, huh?
Look at this!
-Oh, it looks so good.
-Buon appetito.
-Absolutely not. That's mine.
-This is amazing.
You know it's good
when people start fighting.
I know.
That's the hardest part!
The pork loin -- half-inch,
brown both sides,
finish it in the sauce
lightly.
That's the way to do it.
And the sauce
is fresh garlic,
really good olive oil,
really good tomatoes,
dynamite oregano.
Then going in
to the fennel.
The fennel, to me, is really
the highlight of the dish.
HUNTER:
I love the fact you didn't
add a bunch of seasoning.
You just get all the flavor
from the tomato sauce
and the vegetables
and that fennel and the cheese.
It makes you feel good.
The ingredients
and the method
and the style and the Italian
attitude all shine through.
Thank you very much.
Well done.
Don't go anywhere.
"Triple-D Takeout" coming back
for one of my favorites
all the way from the islands.
Okay, clean this up.
Welcome back to
"Triple-D Takeout."
We are in the final leg
of this fantastic adventure.
Invited friends of ours
all the way across the country.
Suzi from
Trina's Starlite Lounge,
Ben from Tocabe,
Giovanni from Andreoli's,
and now my Hawaiian twin,
Chef Glenn.
I did the hair first,
by the way. Just FYI.
This guy, this guy.
-I did it first. I did.
Not him, me.
Chef Glenn has
a funky little joint
in the middle
of a bowling alley.
This is Alley Restaurant
in the Aiea Bowl.
OMG.
Dude, you win Best Oxtail Soup
in the World award.
You can just
get away from me.
[ Growls ]
I ate so much of the oxtail soup
that I had to have a little nap.
This guy crushes it.
Island specialties galore.
Now, I don't want to
repeat ourselves, Glenn,
but we already made oxtail.
Just broth for you.
-You're my broth-er.
-Broth-er.
So that is my famous
lemon crunch cake.
That's a lot of bribery, Glenn.
A lot of bribery.
-What are we into?
-Kalbi short ribs.
-Okay. Kalbi short ribs.
-Boneless short ribs.
-Start us off.
-Soy sauce,
brown sugar
and white sugar,
garlic, ginger.
-Sesame oil.
-Black pepper.
What creates
the liquid-y effect?
We don't have a lot of liquid
in there, Chef.
Oh, he put the wrong soy in.
There's a bigger soy there.
-Okay.
-Now, the kalbi rib's
traditionally
a Korean short rib.
How long will you marinate it
typically at the restaurant?
It's vacuum sealed
so it can
suck all the marinade
into the meat overnight.
This is one portion
for like one human?
Yes.
All right.
While he's doing that,
I'm gonna make
the alley dressing.
So I got the soy sauce in here.
-Okay.
-Garlic.
-Sugar.
Rice wine vinegar.
Regular vinegar. Sesame oil?
Yep. Minced onion.
-A little salt.
-Ginger.
-Hoisin sauce?
-Yes.
-And a little chili flake.
-Did you find the honey?
And I do see the honey,
darling.
[ Laughs ]
Usually we mix it
with a blender.
GUY: All right. Emulsify the oil
into that dressing.
You can add the oil.
Then, Guy, you're gonna take
that mix that you just made
and fold that into the
mayonnaise that I have there.
Yeah, brother.
The kalbi ribs
are in the marinade.
We put it on a charcoal grill.
Fire it up.
-Perfect.
-Oh, yeah.
Beautiful. I mean, they're
short ribs this big, you guys.
I mean, they're monsters.
So this is the alley dressing
for the salad.
Did you
steam off some rice?
-Yes, we did, Chef.
-Put the cabbage on it.
Salad.
Oh, man. Look at that.
"Oh, man"
is exactly right.
GLENN: Kalbi's gonna go
right on to the cabbage.
Take a look at that dish,
huh?
Tell me that
doesn't look fantastic.
♪♪
HUNTER:
Has a lot of flavor.
[ With mouth full ] I can't get
it in my mouth fast enough.
[ Light laughter ]
The balance
of the ingredients,
the freshness
of the ingredients.
Cooked over the charcoal
makes all the difference,
almost candying the marinade
on it.
A little ginger.
Sesame oil is critical to it.
Some greens to kind of
refresh the palate.
It's out-of-bounds. This is
the kalbi rib done right.
And all out of a bowling alley.
And now look at this.
Folks that are fans
of "Triple-D"
can now get
"Triple-D Takeout."
All they got to do
is reach out to you.
And look at the feast
that you sent us.
You guys have rocked it.
So, as you know,
someone's gonna win Best Dish.
It doesn't involve
cash or prizes,
simply bragging rights.
Let me converse
with my constituents,
and we'll be back
in just a moment.
Some background music,
please.
Come on, Piggy. Quit eating.
-One last bite.
-You have a problem.
-I learned a lot today.
Thank you. Appreciate it.
Thanks for sharing.
Glenn, how do I get
some of that oxtail soup?
I can send it to you.
Okay, okay, okay.
Now, listen.
Thank you very much, Glenn.
I love how that comes in.
I want to give everybody
the participation trophy
and say you all did
such a fantastic job.
But we have to come up
with a Best Dish.
Here we go, folks.
The winner of tonight's
"Triple-D Takeout"
is gonna be...
a winner-winner...
...rabbit tostada dinner!
[ Air horn blows ]
Give it up for Tocabe!
♪♪
-Thank you, guys.
-You all did a fantastic job.
I hope all the fans
reach out to you
and get that delivery
going to their house.
They're gonna love it.
You guys have been awesome.
We'll see you next week
on "Triple-D Takeout."
Thank you, guys.
But the finocchio, Guy,
normally to make it nice,
you put the one on top
the other one.
You know.
[ Whistles ]
-Oh. [ Whistles ]
-Totally.
[ Laughter ]