So when I come off the road
from doing "Triple D"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food for my family.
And after a few weeks --
Dad, can we just --
I mean, please.
Go to a restaurant
at least one time.
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea,
how about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner, huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got the kolache queen
of Utah sending us
some sweet and savory.
I'm telling you what, sister,
excellent job.
Authentic Mexican
that can only be done
by my sister Silvana
at Barrio Café in Phoenix.
Get a shot of
how beautiful that is.
And our boy, Kyle Ship,
some Korean pork belly straight
from his Maui food truck.
I am excited for this.
GUY: And my good friends
are Chaps Pit Beef in Maryland
are firing off something
they call the cordon cue.
Are you kidding me?
And on top of it all,
they're gonna
video conference in
to give us the true
"Triple D" experience.
-I like the way you think.
-Exactly.
This is "Triple D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Well, hey, everybody.
Thank you for making it.
We've got Silvana
from Barrio Café,
the one and only Bob --
where's Donna?
Donna's here.
And Donna from Chaps Pit Beef.
We got our buddy Kyle
all the way out on the island
in the truck from
Maui Fresh Streatery.
And of course,
and this is the name
I always get wrong is Devin,
but it's Hruska's Kolaches.
-Did I get it right?
-Yes.
-Nice.
-Good. We can go home now.
Thanks for tuning in.
-Good job.
-Goodbye.
So of course, you guys
know my son Hunter,
but this is my nephew Jules
and my son Ryder
running in the camera.
So let's get into this.
What I've asked you to do
is send me some of your
favorite new recipes.
Just because we're hungry.
We'll cook them,
and by the way,
at the end of this,
someone will get the award
of best dish.
It'll be nothing more
than bragging rights
just so Silvana can call Bob
and say, "Ha, ha."
Ha, ha.
[ Bell dings ]
Silvana, how are things
at Barrio Café these days?
18 years and still at it.
You really have true
representation on that menu
for different regions
of Mexico.
It's really
a cultural experience.
The zarandeado is a Baja dish.
That's some Mayan flavors
right there.
-They're my flavors now.
-Well.
GUY:
Such a wonderful place.
I love all the artistry
that's in there.
Look at the ink.
My sister
from another mister.
When I was there visiting,
somebody came out to the camaro
and gave a little...
[ whistles ]
Dude! What are you doing?
-"Triple D" rules!
GUY: Oh, it funny because
he covered it with plastic.
So when I came walking out,
it was a riot.
Oh, I love that.
All right, here we go.
-Guido, check this out.
-That's sick.
Now you're an honorary cholo.
[ Laughs ] That's awesome.
I'll put it down here
at the "Triple D" Wall of Fame.
What's on the menu?
-Cuali de Cameron.
Cuali means good
in Nahuatl,
which is the original
language of Mexico.
So this is good
eating right here.
Right, but I mean,
what is the dish, actually?
We got the tostada,
roasted jalapeño from Veracruz,
shrimp, avocado slice,
chili oil, and pico.
So give us the rundown.
First thing is
we're gonna get that garlic,
put it in vegetable oil
because you got to get
the chili oil going.
Once the garlic
starts to caramelize,
put all that chili in there.
There's nine chilies
in that oil.
Wow.
That's a lot of chilies.
Guajillo chili going in.
The chiltepin.
This is chili pitin?
Chiltepin,
that is one of the most
fragrant
and flavorful peppers.
Unbelievable.
I've never heard
of that before.
It's...[ speaking Spanish ].
Little, but hot.
GUY: Smells fantastic.
The pasilla, bay leaf,
cinnamon, mustard, salt,
black pepper, juniper,
allspice.
Yep, you got it right.
And a little habanero.
And then you're gonna
just let it steep.
Look at the cheese.
That's from Oaxaca
it's called quesillo --
Mexican street cheese.
I got to feed these guys
before they start eating an arm.
HUNTER:
Good stuff right here.
It's got a little tang,
it's got a little salt. Mm!
Just looking at this chili oil,
it's gonna be hot.
Don't forget to add
that olive oil
and the piloncillo sugar,
did you get that in there?
[ Mumbling indistinctly ]
Piloncillo -- yeah, so that's
a Mexican cone sugar.
GUY: That is the cone sugar,
okay.
Turn off the flame before
you put that booze in there
'cause it's gonna do
a Mexican hat dance.
So this is Mezcal?
Also from Oaxaca.
Watch your eyebrows.
-There we go.
-Nice.
And then you're just gonna
blend them all.
What can we do next, Chef?
Mix your string cheese,
goat cheese, shallot,
and garlic mix,
little salt, little pepper.
Watch that guy you started
on low, low, low because
when it's hot it expands
when you blend it.
-Safety first, guys.
-Oh, yeah.
That's what we are here
at the Fieri house.
[ Laughs ]
I'm waiting for --
he's gonna be wearing it.
[ Laughs ]
GUY: Now I've got some
roasted jalapeños.
I used oak wood
on those peppers.
Stuff this bountifully?
Like, would you want to put it
in your mouth, buddy.
I'm looking pretty
good there, right?
Yep, that's about right.
I'm gonna go ahead
and put these in the oven.
350 degrees?
-Correct.
Just till the cheese
really starts to melt.
Walk me through the shrimp,
chef.
I'm gonna fess up.
Here's your spice mix
for that shrimp.
-Ha, ha!
-Oh.
We got spices.
What do you need?
Paprika, a little salt
and pepper, pan-seared,
get a little color on it,
garlic.
And jalapeños.
Whoo.
When's the longaniza
going in?
Just take a little piece
and cook it off real fast.
What is it?
Longaniza is always pork.
It's usually the same flavor,
but a lot less grease
than a chorizo.
So how are we plating
this up?
So you got the tostada
with the pepper on it.
Shrimp,
a little bit of cream.
What's in the crema?
Heavy cream
and a lot more buttermilk
than you normally
would to make a cream.
We got that.
Pico and avocado slice.
Longaniza on top?
Is there any longaniza left
or did Guy eat it all?
Like this?
I've only done
that a thousand times.
[ Laughs ]
And then the chili oil.
Man, that's sexy.
Ryder, just get a shot
of how beautiful that is.
Hunch over.
There's the hunch.
♪♪
Oh, my gosh.
The jalapeño by itself
is delicious.
Nice and roasted mild.
-Mm, that cheese in there.
Great shrimp,
which Jules cooked perfectly.
Real tangy crema.
But the chili oil
brings it all together.
So you get the crunch,
the cream,
the heat, the chili,
the snap on the shrimp,
I mean, it is out of bounds.
So that's how
we're kicking things off, folks,
here on "Triple D Takeout"
at the Fieri house.
Don't go anywhere. Three other
fantastic chefs coming up.
All right, dibs on Ryder's.
♪♪
So welcome back,
"Triple D Takeout."
We've got Bob and Donna
from Chaps Pit Beef,
Devin from Hruska's Kolaches,
and Chef Silvana
from Barrio Café served up --
how would you describe it?
Mouthful of flavors.
So not to be outdone, though,
our buddy Kyle
all the way from the islands,
from Maui Fresh Streatery.
If you haven't
seen this place,
you've got to check it out.
KYLE: Pohole fern laphet
thock salad
with braised octopus.
Didn't the Beatles
have a song with that now?
I don't know.
-Bro, it's ridiculously good.
-Thank you.
-Oh, my gosh.
-What's up?
You know, Kyle, I think
he's taller than you now.
-He's the same age as Ryder.
-I remember.
[ Laughs ]
Everybody's
a comedian out here.
Whoo!
I'm out.
I'm out?
[ Laughter ]
GUY: All right,
well, let's get into this.
If you can open up
that small box.
You can't
get that over my fat head.
-Good. Got to have one.
-Yeah, there you go.
Take a look at those hats.
Those say ohana on them
and in Hawaiian,
ohana means family.
And, you know,
I really feel like
we're all part
of the "Triple D" family.
Very generous of you, Chef.
And it is the truth.
What's on the menu today?
So we're gonna do
the soul bowl,
which is a crispy
Korean pork belly bowl
with housemade
banchan pickles.
I've got the steamed
white rice going.
Start with the sauce
for the pork belly.
Got it.
Soy sauce,
sesame oil, green chili paste,
our local Hawaiian honey,
gochujang sauce,
which is the Korean
chili sauce.
Simmer for five, 10 minutes.
Chef, how are we going to
prepare the pork belly?
Slice about half inch slabs.
Yep, just like that.
Garlic and ginger can go
into the sauce as well.
And now I can start throwing
this pork belly down?
Yeah, we're gonna want
to get that nice and crispy.
Now, Chef, tell me about
the pork belly.
What did you do to it
before this?
We actually marinate it
in that sauce
that you're making right there
for 48 hours
and then we'll tent it
and put it in the oven
at 325
for about four hours,
drain off the liquid,
and then back in the fridge
for 24 hours.
Yum!
All right,
so we've got a cooked pork belly
with a lot of flavor already.
Now we're putting a sear to it.
-Perfect.
Kimchi, give me the rundown
on making this.
That's about
a two-week process.
Take Napa cabbage,
brine it in salt water,
drain it off,
add a variety of different
spices, garlic, fish sauce,
and that sits out and ferments
for about two or three days.
So what you have there
is you have four different
Korean pickles,
and those pickles
will be accouterments
for your final dish.
Hey, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Don't go international with us
with the accouterment talk.
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Those will be
four garnishes for you.
Thank you very much.
That's some Korean pickled onion
with jalapeño.
How are those made?
Oh, my gosh.
It's just sweet
white onion, sliced jalapeños,
vinegar, soy sauce,
and lemon juice.
Outstanding.
Tell me about the bean sprouts.
What's in here?
Those are quick blanched,
then tossed sesame oil,
Korean dashi, which is
soup base and green onions.
My mouth is watering.
And the pickled
cucumber wakame?
We do a quick sugar brine,
then rehydrated
Japanese wakame seaweed
and then rice wine vinegar
and sugar marinade.
All right, Chef, we've pulled
the majority
of the pork belly here.
Now we can start building
our soul bowls.
We're gonna get a couple
of nice scoops of rice
in each of those bowls.
Put the four banchan
pickles in each bowl.
I am excited for this.
Perfect,
load it right in there.
Three to four pieces of pork
nicely fattened up on top.
Okay.
-Get your finishing sauce.
-Right across the pork.
Ooh!
Finish it with a little bit
of that shaved scallions there.
I already had my chopsticks
out and you're back to work.
Where do you want
the sesame seeds?
Right up on top as well.
Here you go. Dig in, guys.
This is so pleasing
to the eyes.
Can't wait for this.
-Wow.
On the truck,
we oftentimes finish it
with a soft-boiled egg,
but I left that off
just for you.
That would've
ruined it for him.
If we had some island music
going in
the background right now,
I would think that
we're in Hawaii.
I'm telling you right now.
[ Island music playing ]
The crisp on that pork belly
and the marinade on top,
it's delicious.
Bro, I think a lot of times
people look at food truck
and they don't give it all
the respect that it deserves.
But this right here
is a high-end restaurant dish,
delicious,
generous portion of pork belly,
complemented with
a delicious sauce
that doesn't overpower.
Every time you bite
into one of
the different pickles,
you get yourself
a little different flavor.
It's like having five different
dishes at once.
Full blown food coma.
[ Laughs ]
Chef, fantastic.
Out of the park.
Outstanding brother.
While we take a brief nap,
you guys go watch
a few commercials,
check your email,
and when we come back
two more fantastic
"Triple D" OG chefs coming up.
We'll see you in a bit.
I'm wrapping mine up.
-Can we finish this now?
-Have some more.
All right, okay.
Welcome back to sleepy
"Triple D Takeout," I'm Guy,
I don't know
who the other people are.
We're all in a food coma.
We've got Silvana
from Barrio Café,
Bob and Donna
from Chaps Pit Beef,
Kyle from Maui Fresh Streatery.
I gotta tell you, Kyle,
I think go to sleep
was the name of that dish
we just had.
[ Laughs ]
-Devin, you want to go up next?
-Yep,
Okay, now, Devin, she has...
I'm gonna
get it wrong again.
Hruska's Kolaches.
Hruska's Kolaches, right?
-Yes.
Kolache's a recipe
and a delicacy
that comes from Texas,
by the way
of the Czech Republic,
by the way of a crazy girl
and her two brothers that have
this funky joint in Utah.
Kolache is buttery
yeast bread.
And then you can stuff
or top them.
It's a melt in your mouth
dough.
High gluten flour,
egg yolk.
[ Record needle scratches ]
-Excuse me.
-I know I pronounce the L.
And I didn't know it was bad
until I came to college.
Oh, gosh,
it's gonna be on TV.
Here come the boys.
You get an A-plus in
very cool packaging.
Thank you. [ Laughs ]
-Gifts for Guy.
-Oh, my.
I don't know what you
just put on my head.
I bedazzled it so we can be
pop stars together.
♪♪
And bedazzled
pop star microphone
so you can make your own
kitchen soundtrack.
-[ Laughs ]
-Check, check.
♪ Ah ♪
Okay.
Was that a little
singing there?
I just make sound effects.
I'm putting together
a soundtrack.
♪ Ah ♪
Pop.
[ Hums ] Psh, pft.
-You were a fireball.
-[ Laughs ]
So let's walk through this.
I've got Texas frozen dough,
maple frozen dough.
You want to start
with Texan or maple first.
Let's do both
at the same time.
Okay, it's all the same dough,
but it's just different sizes
because you need more dough
for the savory one.
So Hunter's got the smaller
dough, which is the maple.
Okay, you got to make
your maple filling.
What's in the maple
filling here?
Cream cheese and you're gonna
put it in the stand mixer.
Put in the sugar,
cream that together.
All right, what can Jules do?
Take your dough
and you're gonna go --
da, da, da, da, da.
Oh!
Hold the two edges and just,
like, wriggle it out
so it becomes long, perfect.
So then you're gonna
take your smoked house sausage
and you're gonna
put it in the dough.
What kind of sausage?
Beef and pork blend
with fresh sage,
salt and pepper,
and garlic and onion,
and jalapeño pulp,
cheddar cheese,
and then we smoke it.
-Nice, that sounds great.
Yours is too long.
I know,
they're crazy over there.
So it's gonna be more wide,
it's like a rectangle.
Yeah, like a rectangle.
And then that sausage link
is gonna go right on it
and you're gonna pinch,
pinch, pinch, pinch, pinch.
Make sure it seals really well
because the dough's gonna
expand in the oven
and it'll unseal.
There's some excess on the end
I'm gonna take off.
I'm over here
getting the sugar mixed in
with the cream cheese,
you know, creaming it out.
I'm doing good on my side.
-[ Laughs ]
Then you add the yolk.
GUY:
You're such a yolkster.
Regarding the maple one.
You have to press it down.
So take your fingers and go
do, do, do, do, do, do, do.
HUNTER: All right.
Everything has a little noise
and a little dance.
A little ding, ding,
ding, ding, ding, ding, ding.
They explain things better.
This is what I got
for round one.
It looks like a corndog.
-Yeah, it looks pretty good.
-How's that? Is that all right?
-That looks okay.
So do that to all of them.
I feel like I'm not
part of the show anymore.
I feel it's like you talking
to the boys, like,
hey, who's the old guy?
Get him out of the shot.
Can we get these in the oven?
Yeah, the Texans ones
throw them in the oven
for 14 minutes.
So go ahead and add
the powdered sugar
and just add it
in a little at a time
so it doesn't explode
in your face.
I was worried
about my chili oil.
[ Laughs ]
Now you add the maple,
do it like a slow drizzle,
but like a fast drizzle.
So obviously, that perfect in
between of what I'm telling you.
[ Laughs ]
And then you whip it
and you whip it good.
[ Humming ]
She's doing the dances.
All right, next up?
It should be nice and fluffy
and, like, kind of marshmallowy.
And you're gonna
fill the craters.
What about the pecans?
So put them in a star
on top of that maple filling
and then you're gonna
sprinkle the top
with brown sugar.
-Got it.
Okay, so those go in
for eight minutes.
Perfect,
we're gonna go to commercial
and we'll see you
in a little bit.
"Triple D Takeout."
Don't go anywhere.
You're gonna love
the kolaches.
Those look fantastic.
-Whoo!
-Oh, yeah.
Welcome back, Chef Devin sent us
these fantastic kolaches.
We have the Texan,
which is a housemade
cheddar alapana sausage,
and we have the maple.
So here we go.
-You can add the hot sauces.
It's gonna taste funny
with the maple.
Oh, don't do the hot sauce
on the maple, gross.
Which one do you
like the best?
Number two is my favorite.
Unique mixture of dry,
fresh, and pickled peppers.
I like what's going on here.
The sausage is delicious.
The kolache dough,
it's light,
it's tender, but it still
has some texture to it.
That was very tasty.
I'm not a big sweets fan,
but I'll be trying this.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I have one, too, because
I feel left out.
I have FOMO.
And what about the other
three of us?
Silvana,
here you go, Chef.
It's warm. It's creamy.
It's a nice kiss of maple
and a little nuttiness
from that pecan.
It's not overly sweet
and I'll even go in for another
piece of it.
I'm telling you what, sister,
excellent job.
All right, so listen, we need
to clean all this up.
And while we do that,
let's take a moment to watch
one of my favorite "Triple D"
OG joints -- Chaps Pit Beef.
Look at that.
You come to Baltimore.
This is what you better see.
And if you don't
it's not Pit Beef.
-What year did I go there, Bob?
-2008.
The time I went was with Duff,
Duff Goldman and Duff and I
made this sandwich.
It was big.
Look at the bite on it!
Make sure you don't...
lose anything.
Then we came back
for another visit.
I haven't found a joint
like it in the country.
Really good premium meat,
a little bit of seasoning,
cooking over
the lump charcoal.
Slice it.
-You got it.
This is all you sent?
Yeah, well,
we had another box,
but it didn't make
the airplane.
Is that a sign
or a cutting board?
A glass cutting board.
We're gonna get it out
to you real soon.
This looks dangerous.
What are we getting into?
-The cordon cue.
And that is gonna be our
thin sliced pit beef
wrapped around pork barbecue
and deep fry it.
You're gonna be blown away.
-Walk me through this.
Take five slices of that beef
and you're gonna lay them out
in, like, a star pattern.
-Bottom round, right?
-bottom round flats.
How are you doing the pork?
We're braising overnight
in the oven
with a little water, vinegar,
and our barbecue seasoning.
We cover it
with a piece of foil
and let it go
for about 275 degrees
for 12 hours.
Delicious.
Heat it up a little bit.
Because we're gonna
deep fry this
and we don't want to have
to wait for everything to go
all the way through,
that as soon as it gets brown
on the outside,
we're gonna be ready to go.
-Exactly.
-You're pretty smart.
[ Laughs ]
I am a kolache maker now,
so I think you guys probably
look at me differently.
[ Laughter ]
So we'll get it
right in the center.
Cheese is down, one?
Alternate till you get like
a little basket there.
-Like so?
-Exactly.
Go from the flour
to the egg wash
and then from the egg wash
to my favorite
the corn flake crumbs.
Look at this thing.
[ Laughs ]
350 oil.
Lowered in nice and slow,
it'll have a better chance
of staying together for you.
Got it. Got it.
Got it. Got it. Got it.
Put a little bit of that gold
barbecue sauce
on the bottom of the roll.
Slaw is going on this
as well, I assume.
Yes, it is.
So you'll take that dressing.
It's mayo, vinegar, sugar,
pepper, salt.
We go pickles, coleslaw,
cut the sandwich in half,
so you can see all them layers
in there.
-Are you kidding me?
-There you go.
-Oh, man.
-This is gonna hurt.
Dude. [ Laughs ]
I'm dying over here, Bob,
I'm dying.
[ Laughter ]
This takes a pulled
pork sandwich
to a whole new level.
-That's for sure.
This takes pit beef sandwich
to a whole new level.
This takes chicken fried steak
It's the greatest of the pit
beef meets the pulled pork.
Oh.
I just ate half the sandwich,
a tostada and a half,
a kolache,
and a big bowl of rice
with pork belly on it.
Ladies and gentlemen, if I was
walking close to the ocean,
EPA would push me back in.
[ Laughter ]
Now, remember, someone is gonna
get best dish
and that involves no cash
or prizes,
simply just bragging rights.
Let me talk with my team
and see who wins. Hold tight.
The prize for winning is
you must send your food to me.
Oh, nice. There you go.
All right,
ladies and gentlemen,
I got to tell you,
it wasn't unanimous,
but we can only have
one winner today.
There's no losers
were all winners.
That all goes to...
winner, winner...
Korean pork bowl dinner.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Congratulations, Kyle.
Well done.
Thank you, guys.
You guys are all awesome.
For everybody at home,
remember,
you can get to these restaurants
or call them or email them,
but you can probably have
these dishes at your doorstep
in the next few days.
That's how we do it
on "Triple D Takeout."
Adios. Thank you, guys.
-We're out!
-All right, so --
-Whoo!
Ooh.
Oh!
Whoo!
Oh.
[ Laughter ]