So, when I come off the road
from doing "Triple-D,"
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks...
Dad, can we just,
I mean, please, go to
a restaurant at least one time?
...they start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner? Huh?
I like that idea.
GUY: And I know
some "Triple-D" joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got Audrey Jane's
take on pizza
coming from
Boulder, Colorado...
There is so much flavor
embedded in that.
That's just ridiculous.
GUY: ...some gangster Greek
from my buddy at Niko Niko's
in Houston...
I'm forgetting that we're even
doing a show right now
'cause I'm feeding
so fast.
...A Cuban melt from
the Grilled Cheeserie
in Nashville...
You guys just hit it
out of the park every time.
...and unforgettable
Uncle Lou in Memphis
is sending us
a fried chicken feast.
I want to
drink the sauce.
And on top of it all, they're
gonna video-conference in
to give us the true
"Triple-D" experience.
I like the way you think.
Exactly.
This is
"Triple-D Takeout."
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
♪♪
Well, there are
some smiling faces.
How is everybody?
-Hi.
-Hi, Guy.
We've got Lou from Uncle Lou's
Fantastic time there.
I fell on the floor.
I'll tell you that story later.
And then, of course,
Dimitri,
the one and only
over at Niko Niko's in Houston.
Crystal and Joseph
over at the Grilled Cheeserie.
But wait a second.
Where's the truck?
Man, it's cruising
neighborhoods,
just finding anybody
who wants to eat.
And then Audrey Jane from
Audrey Jane's Pizza Garage,
a fantastic pizza joint.
You're the newbie
of the group.
Hi, guys.
I know that Dimitri
and Lou
were on the show
a long time ago.
I think Lou
was on the show
when we shot this
in black-and-white film.
Take our first family photo.
-[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]
We asked you to send us a dish
that you've been working on
that Hunter and I
will cook.
So anyhow,
here's my son Hunter.
Here's my son Ryder.
And welcome to
the Fieris' backyard.
And, Dimitri,
you up first?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Go grab it.
Niko Niko's in Houston
is such a fun place,
and there's so much energy.
The lamb shank
with potatoes.
Mmm. You're going to have
to take this away.
I wasn't serious.
No? [ Laughs ]
Okay,
just so you understand,
it's a half-hour show,
and you sent four boxes.
By the way,
this is my nephew Jules.
-How's it going, guys?
-Of the people that enjoy food,
I think Jules enjoys it
more than anyone.
This is a good start
if we've got skewers.
-Alright.
-Skewers.
Is this really
a T-shirt that you guys sell?
"Check out
my Greek honey balls"?
Hey,
that's for you, man.
Loukoumades.
Greek honey balls.
You just crank it, and it just
pops out little doughnuts.
I want that on the back
of the '67.
[ Imitates machine ]
You want all the honey
to get in there.
Those are your culinary buoys
in the shipyard of Flavortown.
Oh, those are crazy.
They are over the top.
Somebody wants to say hi.
You didn't have her
when I was there.
No, she's new.
We named her after
the restaurant -- Nicoletta.
-Nicoletta?
-Yes.
Nice to meet you.
Alright. Pork kebabs.
Am I marinating this meat?
Yes.
Oil for the marinade.
Black pepper.
Salt, garlic.
Greek oregano.
From my island, Syros.
Some seasoned salt.
Now, what can Hunter
and Jules be doing
while I'm working on this?
Why don't they make
the Tzatziki sauce?
Get the Greek yogurt,
the sour cream,
pepper, salt, the garlic,
olive oil.
-Cucumber?
-Yeah, the cucumber.
Make sure that all the water
is drained out of there.
HUNTER: Okay.
Just put everything
in there and combine.
Dimitri, you sent me pork butt
that was cubed?
Correct. That's going to go
in the marinade.
Okay.
Put it in the refrigerator
after you mix it all together.
Looks dynamite. Are you making
these pitas, Dimitri?
No, no.
We have a guy from New York
that makes those
pita breads for us.
How many pitas you guys
go through in a week?
12,000.
Put it on the grill
a little bit.
GUY: What else do we have that
should be getting done?
Let's get the fries
in there.
Now, those have
already been blanched.
Just finish those off.
Already grated
the cheese for you.
Where's the cheese
going to go, Chef?
That's going to go after
you fry the fries
and you season them
with the Greek stuff.
Then you just put
a mound of cheese
right on top of the fries.
Yeah, that's where
cheese belongs.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's up your alley.
What type of cheese is this,
Chef?
It's called kefalotyri.
Oh, that's what
I was going to call it too.
I thought we've tried
all the cheeses.
You've got to send us
some of that
so we can put it
on a sandwich.
You know, the Greeks
are the number-one
consumers of cheese
in the world.
-That's our next location.
-We better get on it.
-You got to find a spot for us.
-Let's go. I'll show you around.
Alright. I've got some of
this pork going down.
-Beautiful.
-Looks good.
Ryder just gets in there
with that.
That's a lot of skewers,
Dimitri.
You should send some over
to Boulder for me.
They look delicious.
Let's make the lemon oil.
That's pretty simple.
That's lemon juice,
salt, pepper, oregano,
Greek extra virgin olive oil.
-Alright.
-Whisk that real good,
then pour it on the kebabs
after they're finished.
I saw that toss and catch,
Hunter.
I like that.
Alright.
So here's the deal.
Dimitri, thank you very much for
sending me enough pork kebabs
to feed your family,
my family,
and then whoever else
wanders into our backyard.
So we're going to take
a little break right now.
Don't worry, Dimitri.
I won't burn the pork.
-Thanks.
-I'll see you in a bit.
Welcome back.
A little "Triple D Takeout."
We've got Crystal and Joseph
over at the Grilled Cheeserie,
Audrey Jane from
Audrey Jane's Pizza Garage,
and our buddy Lou
from Uncle Lou's.
Got my nephew Jules
and Hunter
helping me out here
in the kitchen.
And we're cooking up
more Greek pork kebabs
than I think that
we anticipated.
How does this look
so far,
our buddy Dimitri
from Niko Niko's?
-Beautiful.
-Good.
I've got the other 76 of them
still cooking over here,
so I'll be at those
in just a second.
Okay,
so some delicious pita
that you have brought in
from New York.
Guy, put the pita
underneath the kebabs
so the juice
can get into the bread.
Uh-huh.
Now take the lemon oil
that you made.
Put it right on top.
Nice drizzle.
I am known
for my precise drizzling.
A little salt and pepper
there, Guy.
Take the oregano that I gave you
and just crush it.
-So you got the fries, right?
-Yep.
Now I just put
a whole bunch of cheese on top.
Oh, yeah.
And where does the Tzatziki
come into play?
Tzatziki
goes on everything.
Now you got to
have a beer.
Yeah, not right now.
We still got to visit
other restaurants.
You're just trying to tamper
his taste for ours, aren't you?
You can do it just like
you're making a little sandwich
or just take it
right off the stick.
Wow.
With the fries on it, too.
And yeah.
There you go.
Yes, good.
Wow. Speechless.
That was so good.
Great pork.
You got to do that on barbecue
if you get that
barbecue flavor for sure.
But then you get this nice fresh
feeling from the Tzatziki.
Come here, Gramps.
There you go.
You got three generations.
Yeah, that's my dad, Jim.
-Jim.
-Hey, Jim.
I'm forgetting that we're even
doing a show right now
'cause I'm feeding
so fast.
And Hunter's
exactly right.
Doing this on the grill
is really the key.
It caramelizes up beautiful.
The fries are fantastic.
And the cheese that I don't know
the name of.
Kefalotyri.
You get that nice
Tzatziki clean-up
with the shredded cucumber
in there.
Refreshes palate. Boom.
You go in for another bite.
Sometimes it's hard
to take the restaurant
out of the restaurant,
take it home,
and have the experience,
but it couldn't feel any better.
Man,
you did an outstanding job.
Thank you so much, guys.
Alright. Let me introduce
one of the newest members
of the "Triple D" family.
Audrey Jane's Pizza Garage
is a funky little pizza joint
that rocks.
The sausage is great.
The oregano is dynamite.
The right-size pepperoni.
The roasted jalapeños.
I can't find anything
I don't like.
Watch out for her.
Wow. I know what that is.
Thank you. We always need
a good pizza peel.
Actually, if you open it up,
there's a brush as well.
HUNTER: Awesome.
Tell us
what you sent us.
Today
you're going to be making
an amatriciana grandma pie.
A what?
It's an amatriciana.
I call it Patty style
at my place
because my mom used to make it
when I was little.
My mom's name is Patty.
I should have said that first.
Let me get the rundown,
because I know when we get into
this kind of a pie tin,
we're making
a Roman-style pizza, correct?
Rome is a little bit different.
It's a little bit airier.
So this is a grandma style,
which you're going to push out
and let rise.
We're doing 100% sourdough.
Okay.
Stretch the pizza,
oil up that pan,
and then sprinkle
your sesame seeds.
And then lay the dough
inside of that?
You got it.
That looks good.
And after you get
that dough in there,
you're going to rub
some more oil on top.
And you really want to press
from the middle
of the dough into the corners.
You want to let this proof
for how long?
I say about two hours.
You want it to be
nice and fluffy.
Okay, so the reason
that you sent me this
is to make me
go through all the work.
But in the meantime, you've
already set me a parbaked.
[ Laughter ]
You got it.
Oh, wow.
Look at the focus.
-Wow.
-Yeah.
Goodness.
So now we're back to taking
one of the parbaked,
which is great
because people that are thinking
about ordering this...
That parbake is key.
-Gorgeous.
-Nice.
Nice toasted sesame seeds.
-That looks beautiful.
-See that?
So now we're going to make
our amatriciana sauce.
Render up that guanciale.
I love all the cheek fat
that's going to be in this.
And once that's rendered,
add that onion in there.
Garlic going in
in just a minute?
Yeah,
I don't want it to burn.
Got it.
Got it. Got it.
Add your SuperDolce.
It's like a tomato paste.
And about three cups
of tomato sauce?
Exactly.
Now, there should be
some containers of chili flakes,
salt, and black pepper.
Okay.
Let that cook down
for like a minute,
and you're going to whisk
that heavy cream in.
Now, "whisk"
way does he go?
[ Rim shot ]
-Wow.
Thank you.
[ Laughs ]
Now we're going to
put the pie together.
What temp should I have that
oven rolling at, Audrey?
Crank that bad boy
up to 575.
And how much sauce we want
on here, sister?
Oh, oh, wait. We're going to
top it with some cheese first.
But that's okay.
There can be some sauce
under the cheese.
-Uh-oh.
-We're talking.
You're moving
too fast for me.
We're talking.
I can't keep up with you.
You should see a package
of sliced mozzarella.
Make sure it's covering
the whole pie,
and also you want it really
into the cracks of the pan.
You want
that cheese crust.
It's all about
the cheese crust.
Stripe that sauce on.
Just like diagonal stripes
all the way down.
Really making this
look easy.
You can just cover it.
Just cover it.
You're going to lay
the caramelized onions
on top of the sauce.
And the pre-cooked bacon now
going on after that?
You got it.
This thing is
getting out of control.
That's going in
the oven now.
Since it's parbaked,
probably about 10 minutes.
Well, there you have it,
ladies and gentlemen.
We're going to take
a small commercial break,
clean things up,
take a brief nap,
and that pizza will be done.
We'll see you in bit here on
"Triple D Takeout."
Alright.
I get the first lounge chair.
You guys are going --
You guys go to the hammock.
Welcome back to
"Triple D Takeout"
here at the Fieri house.
We've got Crystal and Joseph
over at the Grilled Cheeserie,
Dimitri over at Niko Niko's
in Houston,
the one and only Lou
at Uncle Lou's,
our friend Chef Audrey
from Audrey Jane's Pizza Garage.
Audrey has just walked us
through probably
one of the more complicated
pizzas we've ever done,
but it is well worth it.
Let me tell you.
That looks done.
-Oh, yeah.
-Man, I'm starving.
Pecorino
and hand-torn basil?
Yep, and hit it
with a splash of chili oil.
Cut it up.
Guy need those scissors
for his hair too.
Watch yourself, Joe.
You haven't even gone yet.
Mmm, I like the thickness of
this compared to super thin.
I don't have to eat
six or seven pizzas.
I like the volume.
Oh, the volume.
The sesame seed
on the bottom -- gangster.
And guanciale
in the cream sauce --
You get that nice creaminess
from it.
A good amount of cheese,
and I love the skirt
that it builds
falling off the side of it.
Between
the salty of the bacon,
the sweet of
the caramelized onion,
and then the chickity-chow
out of that chili oil...
There is so much flavor
embedded in that.
That's just ridiculous.
Well, I'm glad
it was worth the wait, boys.
When he gets
his happy dance going on,
that's when you know
he likes it.
No, that was
my burning my mouth dance.
I want to remind you guys,
at the end of this,
my distinguished panel
of assistants,
of sous chefs,
and camera operators
will make a decision of who
is going to get best dish.
And let me remind you, that does
not involve cash or prizes,
just simple
bragging rights.
And by the way, Audrey Jane,
it looks like Hunter and I
are the farmer.
[ Laughter ]
I love it.
But not to be outdone,
now it's time to take
a road trip from the food truck
into the restaurant
with the grilled cheese team.
Yeah,
that's how you do it.
This is so good.
I'm gonna go into, like,
a little dream sequence.
GUY: Three restaurants now and
still the grilled cheese truck.
This is gourmet
right here, man.
Trace Adkins.
He came to the truck.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
House-made pimento cheese,
local cheddar, macaroni.
He reads the menu and makes it
sound like a country song.
Doesn't get any better
than that.
Look at this.
Three small boxes.
Well done.
Oh, that is money.
We heard you didn't have
a butter wheel.
CRYSTAL:
We felt like you needed one.
We're having, like, a little
mini Christmas in July.
Yeah,
it's a cast-iron press.
Someone gets to put
that together now.
Thank you, guys.
What are we making?
Our Cubano melt.
You're going to be making
the mojo mustard
and the chili honey glaze
that's going to glaze
our pulled pork.
Walk me through
how the pork's made.
We brine it for 12 hours
in orange juice, lime juice,
Tennessee whiskey, and spices,
herbs, garlic.
And then we roast it
five hours.
Sorry, I've got
the two mental giants over here
that are working
on the sandwich press.
You actually
won't even need that.
Yeah, you won't
actually need that
'cause you have that press
that we sent you.
That's the Camaro of
the grilled cheese presses.
That's the Camaro.
That's the '68.
Let's talk about
the chili glaze
that's going on top of this.
That's toasted
Chile de Arbol.
Very, very spicy.
Take the honey,
and you're going to squeeze
a couple limes in there.
Bring that up to a simmer,
and then toss all that glaze
in the pork.
Into the oven?
Yeah, brick oven.
Alright, so while that's going,
anything else?
Let's make
the mojo mustard.
I sent you herby mustard
already made
and then
mojo pork reduction.
So that is
the braising liquid
from the pork
that's been cooked.
Alright.
How do we build the sandwich?
So that bread
you have there,
that's made here on Music Row
by Bobby John Henry.
Bobby John Henry.
He's making that
special for us.
He's putting lard in there.
So it really stands up.
Alright, any special story
about the cheese?
Jimmy Jack Johnson,
did he make the cheese?
Jack didn't do it.
So we hit the --
on the outside or inside?
-Outside.
-The outside of the bread.
-The other outside.
-I asked you.
The other outside.
The slices of cheese down.
Everything goes
in between the cheese.
We've got delicious rosemary
shaved ham.
And then mojo pork.
I would do mojo mustard
on top of the pulled pork
so it can, like,
soak in.
Pickles on top.
And then you're going to
top it with that cheese.
You got to cut them in half,
because that way, the cheese,
it just melts faster.
Grill at about 450.
Get the shot on this,
Ryder.
Wait, are you making
all three at -- No.
Does it have on lock,
or do I just stand here and make
Jules hold it for an hour?
Well, usually we're not
making that many
on the single like that.
We're untrained
professionals.
That should take about
between two and three minutes.
But since we put three
monster sandwiches on it,
do we have enough time
to go to commercial?
Yeah.
Of course we have time
to go to commercial.
We got another fantastic chef
coming up
after we try these.
"Triple D Takeout."
See you in a minute.
-Don't leave.
-I'm not.
I'm just watching the grilled
cheese. You guys clean up.
Welcome back.
"Triple D Takeout."
I've got Hunter,
Ryder running the camera,
and we have a special cameo
from my nephew Jules.
We've had great pie
from Audrey Jane's Pizza Garage,
fantastic grilled pork from
Dimitri over at Niko Niko's,
and our friends
at the grilled cheese truck
have just delivered Cuban pork
with this wonderful bread
made by who?
What was the guy's name again?
Bobby John Henry.
Bobby John Henry bread,
because everybody knows
they love that.
-Oh, wow. Look at that.
-Oh, yeah.
What are we thinking?
The bread's dynamite
and the press?
You get a ton of heat into it,
a ton of cheese in it.
Saltiness of that ham,
love the rosemary crust on it,
and the richness of the pork
with this sweet heat
from the chili honey.
You guys just hit it
out of the park every time.
So fantastic job.
But not to be outdone,
this guy is a one of a kind.
Here in Memphis, Tennessee.
It's a place called Uncle Lou's.
And he's doing chicken,
one of my favorite ways,
fried and dipped.
Wow, man.
If you live within 300 miles
of this joint,
you should be getting
yourself over here.
Well, Lou, I got to tell you,
I appreciate everything
about that fantastic
chicken experience.
And I'm more happy that
we just kept out of the brief
bit of footage of me falling.
Oh, wait, you fell?
I thought Lou fell.
Oh, I fell bad.
Oh, don't run it now.
Anybody see that fall?
[ Laughter ]
I think I just bought
the chicken farm.
I was gonna ask you if you had
slip-resistant shoes on today.
Slip-resistant shoes?
No, I got flip-flops on today.
It's getting
that kind of hot.
Lou, what did you send us?
You remember?
What is this?
That is not a pot.
That is the pot.
That is the day we went from
no longer honey-dipped,
sweet, spicy love.
Like a barbecue sauce.
No, more like
a Buffalo wing sauce.
That's like
sweet spicy love.
Note that.
Name change.
What, did you mail everybody
Sweet Spicy Love?
-Oh, my gosh.
-Representing.
Oh, yeah, I'm already working
on my Spicy Love pizza.
Love you, brother.
That's awesome.
Okay, so how do you want
to start this?
Let's go with the vinegar
in the pot.
Get it warm.
Red wine vinegar.
Those two containers,
that's the correct amount
of corruption.
GUY: It's called
the corruption?
Once you've tasted it,
you've been corrupted.
GUY: So we're going to make
some corruption right here.
Salt,
granulated garlic,
celery salt, some chili powder,
and hickory smoke.
The corruption's in.
Honey and hot sauce,
and it's over with.
I love it. Who's there
hanging out with you today?
These are a couple of
my daughters and my grandkids.
What a proud grandpa, man.
I am.
Trust me.
Alright, Lou,
walk me through this.
The seasonings
that you have there,
got to add it
to the flour.
The salt, onion powder,
garlic powder.
And you know
what that secret is.
You told me yourself.
Cinnamon.
Hey.
You're right. It was that little
kiss of that cinnamon.
That's from
my great-grandmother.
We're going to dredge
the chicken in the flour,
go to the fryer?
That's it.
Five minutes.
And I can do the pickles
with this, correct?
Correct.
Oh, you're frying
those pickles?
We have chicken-fried steak,
chicken-fried chicken,
so why not
chicken-fried pickles?
What's going on
with these carrots?
You dump them right in the oil
when your chicken comes out.
We're going to
fry the carrots?
We in the South, man.
This is the South.
If it ain't fried,
it ain't right, so...
[ Laughter ]
Let's put this together.
The carrots get topped
with the corruption?
Correct.
Jules read the recipe.
Way to go, Jules.
Put it in
the Sweet Love sauce,
then hit it with
corruption salt.
[ Laughs ]
Ooh.
Hey, that cinnamon on there,
oh, man.
Wow, that pickle
was pickle-y.
[ Laughter ]
I told you.
I've told people
about your approach
to making great chicken.
You start with
simple ingredients,
highest quality,
that you treat right.
Oh, my God.
I want to drink the sauce.
[ Laughs ]
-Oh, oh, God. Oh.
[ Laughter ]
Well, here's the deal,
buddy.
Lou, it's fantastic.
Delicious chicken. Legit.
I appreciate your sharing
with everybody,
all of you chefs
sharing with us all.
Oh, there he goes.
Look at this.
-Nice.
-Dimitri.
I like it, Dimitri.
We put some of our Love sauce
on our tater tots.
We got to
come to a decision.
So give me a moment as I deal
with my constituents
and figure out
who it's going to be.
Step on over here, folks.
-Oh, man.
-They got the huddle.
It's awesome, man.
Good job, baby.
Man, it's so good.
I get why you're a legend, Lou.
Yeah.
I got to tell you something.
It was a four-way tie,
but we can only have one winner,
which again, includes no cash
or prizes here
on "Triple D Takeout,"
and the winner winner
goes to the...
chicken dinner.
Uncle Lou's,
congratulations.
You all did a fantastic job.
We'll see you guys
next week
on "Triple D Takeout."
-Thank you.
-You guys are awesome.
Adios.
♪♪
That hurt, by the way.
I hope you cut that
Watch out if there's a menu
on the floor.
You could fall.
Happened earlier.
You saw it.