Hey, Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
This trip...
Whoa.
...we're filling up...
So much going on here.
...on Philadelphia.
Are these guys too good
to be true?
That means righteous wings...
Give it the love.
...cheesesteaks with a twist...
It's unique. I don't think
I've ever had anything like it.
...South Philly Indonesian...
This is the Indonesian Embassy
of Flavortown.
...and three crazy brothers...
Nice, nice
Yeah.
...bringing something new
to the neighborhood
Italian.
You're getting all
the flavor you want.
Wham!
That's all right here
right now on "Triple-D."
♪♪
I love coming to the East coast,
I mean, all these big cities,
they've got so much character,
so much history,
and I'm here on the east side
of Philadelphia
in the Port Richmond area.
A lot of people like to call
this the Polish capital, Philly.
I'm here to check out a joint
where two real estate buddies.
Came upon a great deal
on a pub and they said,
"Hey, why don't we get
into the pub
and restaurant business?"
You're going to dig it.
This is the Gaul & Co.
Malt House.
♪♪
We're up. We
got Chicken Cutlet.
Gaul & Co. Malt House
is your usual corner bar,
but like at the next level.
A recipe
for the side salad.
Everybody comes in to have
a good time, good food.
FIERI: And the dudes serving up
all those goods,
that'll be Joe Forkin
and Jim Lyons
and Matt Yeck,
some real characters
who gave this casual spot
a formal name.
The Gaul & Co. Malt House.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
What did you call it?
Gaul & Co. Malt House.
[ Fast ]
That's how we answered
the phone call --
Gaul & Co. Malt House.
[ Mumbles ]
Are these guys
too good to be true?
I don't even care
what the food taste like.
I just want to hang out
with these two guys.
When I tell people the menu,
I tell them how great it is.
The wings,
It's our favorite.
Buffalo Wings,
Bar seats seven.
Buffalo's perfect heat.
I can eat these
seven days a week
if my wife would let me.
One of the specialties
is wings in the house?
Yeah, chicken wings. And then we
make them with a lot of love.
[ Laughing ] Alright.
Give it the love.
Crushed red pepper,
onion powder, black pepper,
salt, sugar,
granulated garlic.
Thank you
for the enunciation.
Cayenne pepper,
chopped fresh garlic, water.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's a homemade whisk.
No.
[ Laughs ]
I found it in the trash
across the street
a couple of years ago.
Onions. Now we pour our brine
over the wings.
It sits overnight in the walk-in
and we'll bake the chicken
375 degrees for 90 minutes.
What sauce are we going to make
to go with the wings?
I'm going to
do buffalo sauce.
Give me the rundown.
Some clarified butter here.
Can you clarify what
you're saying about that?
No. This is totally
unclarified.
Very nice.
Granulated garlic.
Fresh garlic.
Salt, sugar, onion powder,
coarse black pepper,
which is better
than regular.
Of course it is.
Cayenne pepper,
crushed red pepper.
Squeeze the lemons,
dropping this lemon in there.
Okay.
Ketchup,
barbecue sauce, hot sauce.
Where did the recipes
come from?
Recipes come from me
and Jim being too fat guys
and sitting down
and saying we'll taste good.
[ Laughs ]
Me and Jim,
two fat guys.
I think the two fat guys know
what they're doing.
The wings come out there,
then we're going to fry them.
Just put a crisp to them,
toss in the sauce.
There you go.
Because you're breaking
the wing in the brine,
you have tender, juicy,
moist chicken.
At the same time,
we've got a good crunch
and it's a buffalo sauce
that's not overly spicy.
It's not just one note.
I'm impressed.
It's the love.
Well done.
Malt House wings,
Buffalo.
I think they're amazing.
The wing sauce
is like perfectly balanced,
little zippy.
Hey, ladies.
How is everything?
Matt and Jimmy are excellent.
They take care of you.
How did you guys meet?
We grew up the block
and a half from each other.
I went to high school
with Jimmy,
and is father-in-law
was my wrestling coach.
He did a good job.
Eddie's in MMA and has fought
just about everybody.
and has fought
I love my downtime
in between fights.
I have a couple drafts
and kind if indulge
a little bit
with Wit Or Witowski.
Got a Wit up, table one.
WOMAN: The Wit Or Witowski is
their take on the cheesesteak.
It's classy, which is tying
into our Polish neighborhood.
It's amazing.
Now,
what are we into?
The Wit Or Witowski.
That's what it's called.
So, in Philly
you get cheesesteak
with onions
or without onions?
We added a "ski" on the end
so now we Polishized.
The with or without.
Wit Or Witowski.
So Kielbasa is the meat
of the Polish people.
And you're going to make
your own Kielbasa.
Paprika, onion powder,
coarse black pepper,
salt, fresh garlic.
Different than granulated garlic
which we're adding now.
Into the ground pork.
Now, this is going
to get mixed up...
with these man hands.
With these man hands,
got it.
We're going to throw
right in the oven
400 degrees
for two hours.
What's up next?
House made cheese sauce.
Butter, chicken stock
that we strain
when we cook the wings.
Got it.
Granulated garlic, onion powder
and the coarse black pepper.
I'm going to whisk it with this
professional whisk we got here.
And what's going on
with the cheese here?
So that's a sharp
American cheese.
I like it.
So this is
the Kielbasa loaf.
Slice it almost
like lunch meat.
Like a what?
Like a lunch meat.
Deli meats.
What do you call them?
Lunch, lunch meats.
Lunch meats.
We launch it
into your mouth.
Who would have thought
of Kielbasa launch meat?
And these your house cut fries
double fried?
There you go.
Add some caramelized onions
right on that.
Finish it off
with the cheese sauce.
Okay.
Look like a pork roll,
but it's a Kielbasa.
Pork roll.
It's delicious.
It's unique,
I don't think I've ever had
anything like it.
It is part ham and cheese,
it is part cheese steak.
There's those big flavors
that you get in Kielbasa,
and the uniqueness
of how you do it
for making it into the loaf,
to slicing it,
to doing it on the flat top,
kind of caramelizing
the sausage.
That is a destination
sandwich.
I'll take a whole pound
for that.
Okay.
You're going to put on
a few pounds if you eat that.
I lowered myself one a month
at this point.
There's no way that even begin
to be true about that.
Nah. You're -- I lied.
[ Laughter ]
Wit Or Witowski.
The Kielbasa so crispy,
and with the onions
got a really rich flavor.
Is it okay that they're taking
the most prized possession
in the sandwich world,
the Philly cheesesteak,
and doing this funky
Polish spin to it?
Everybody loves it,
so obviously it's...
Oh, everybody
should love it.
I mean, when you make
your own launch mean...
[ Laughter ]
YECK: Kielbasa egg rolls up.
MAN: I bring a lot
of my friends in here.
They've all always
had a great time.
It's definitely more than a
neighborhood bar.
Gaul & Co. Malt House.
Yeah, come on down.
We'll see you there.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next,
a Philadelphia trio...
I'm just dying to see
the end of this,
...taking over a tavern...
It's Flavor City.
...and bringing mama's recipes
to the table.
That's exactly
how I like it.
♪♪
So, I'm here in South Philly,
but I always want to come here
because it reminded me
of great Italian food,
lots of stories, lots of family,
and I found joint that's
serving up just that.
They're serving up
their mom's recipes
in an old neighborhood bar.
This is Stogie Joe's.
SERVER: Chicken parm,
table five.
If you're coming to look
for that Italian vibe,
this is the place to be.
It's got a world class menu,
but it's got
a neighborhood feel.
Order up, linguine
with olive and garlic.
MAN: I remember coming here
when I was a kid,
but around 10 years ago,
new two brothers
took it over.
Little neck clams.
I knew Sonny from
when I was a kid.
He's basically the host here.
And then you got Stogie Joe,
who's just an all-around guy.
Then you got Kristian,
who's a fabulous cook.
FIERI: But this is
the brother's first rodeo.
They teamed up
on a more upscale spot,
but decided to jump
from fine dining
into this long time
local joint.
It's kind of like a speakeasy.
The old man was selling.
He was retiring,
so he says,
"I want you guys to have it.
I think you'd be perfect
for you."
FIERI: What do you guys
serve here?
What was on our dinner
table every day.
I lost my mom
eight months ago.
That's all her recipes
over the wall.
Spaghetti and meatballs,
the crab gravy.
Order up, linguine
and crag gravy.
Nobody makes the crab gravy
like Stogie Joe.
Sunday, gravy was a tomato sauce
for a pasta dish, correct?
Exactly.
But we're going
to make it with crab.
Yep. So we start with olive oil,
butter, leeks, onion.
Celery, bay leaf.
Garlic, peppercorn,
a little bit oregano,
crushed red pepper,
some fresh parsley and thyme.
My favorite album.
Get that going
for a few minutes.
Raw but clean blue crabs.
Exactly.
And this is the crab
of the East Coast.
Yes.
Talk about great flavor
and sweet.
Old bay, and then we'll cook it
for 15 minutes.
We'll finish it with white wine
and fresh plum tomatoes.
We're going to cook it?
Yep.
Four hours, five hours.
Oh, really?
Yup. We macerated it
for our food.
I've never seen this.
That's awesome.
So it comes with the soup
and everything?
Yeah.
Going to grind it up.
Get the sauce out of it.
Yep.
[ Laughs ]
The crab, all that great
flavor's in the shell.
You'll get all the flavor,
none of the shells.
Exactly.
This is the next level.
Did your mom get the chance
to see any of this?
Absolutely.
What did she say?
"I never taught it
to you this way."
Exactly.
I'm just dying to see
the end of this.
Crab gravy,
add the tomato,
butter just to balance out.
Bring it up temperature,
then add the linguine,
the salt and pepper.
Just coat it real nice.
Real nice like that.
Smells the part.
Finish it
with a little parsley,
extra virgin olive oil.
And that's all she wrote.
In South Philly, we eat it
with bread. You got to dip.
Your brothers aren't over here
serving the bread,
working together
as a tag team.
Here you go, big guy.
I was sleepy.
Thank you.
Oh, you taking a nap where you?
It is crab on crab on crab.
You're getting all
the flavor you want.
Wham,
right into the pasta dish.
It's Flavor City.
Really delicious.
Two linguine, crab.
The crab gravy
is really, really good.
The crabs just threw out
that sauce,
and it's unforgettable.
Order up, sausage bites.
MAN: It's the kind of place
where I always say
the next day I want it again.
Is the food different in
South Philly to North Philly?
It really is really, yeah.
Really?
It just feels like more
authentic,
just has like a better taste
and a better vibe to it.
So this is like no, no --
This is like being at home.
I'm ordering the same food
that I've been eating
for like 60 years.
And I come over here and say,
"Wow, it's so much better
and different."
FIERI: Like this new take
on an Italian classic.
Stogie Joe Pizza.
The absolute best pizza
in South Philadelphia.
FIERI: And making it can be
just as much fun as eating it.
-Oh, that's right.
-Aah!
And we got more of that
when we come back.
-We basically --
-Hold on one second.
MAN:
I got a dead light, guys.
Dead light?
You kidding me?
[ Laughter ]
Dead light?
I'm right in the rhythm here!
We got a dead light!
If you're not pointing
at six people at one time,
If not, you're not
in South Philly.
Welcome back. "Triple D"'s
hanging out in South Philly.
This isn't Stogie Joe.
This is Stogie Joe's brother.
And Stogie Joe
doesn't smoke cigars,
but he got the name
when he was a kid.
Because if you're in
South Philly
and you don't have a nickname
like he didn't have one,
but his other brother did,
that's Sonny Boy and Stogie Joe
and Kristian.
-[ Laughs ]
-How was that?
Great job.
That's the way your brother
explained it to me.
Everybody in South Philly
has a nickname, but this one.
I need three linguine
in crab gravy all day, George.
It's a fun pub,
but it's got grandma's food.
You can get a pasta dish that is
just as good as anywhere else
and a pizza that's completely
different from any other pizza
that you're going to get.
Stogie Joe pizza.
I had the Stogie Joe pizza
today.
Phenomenal.
Soppressata, salami.
The cheese on the bottom, sauce
and toppings are on the top.
A lot of people
get confused with that.
Nobody in the city
makes a pizza like that.
We're going to do
a Stogie Joe Pizza.
Basically a salsa cruda,
mozzarella on the bottom,
on the dough.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Stays on the dough
nice, nice.
You know?
Nice, nice?
Yeah.
I'm going to get
all the lingo down.
It's a square pizza.
Is square a Philly thing?
That's the way we do it.
-We're going to make the dough.
-Yeast.
Water. Philly water
makes the best pizza.
That's what it is?
High-gluten flour.
Yeah, we use
high-gluten flour.
How long are we going
to get this mix?
7 to 10 minutes or so.
We're going to let it proof.
Portion it out?
Yeah.
Come here, guys.
Who's the best at portioning out
the dough?
Yeah, he's the best.
Oh, we've got to see this?
How close do you think
he's going to get
the first round?
It takes the second
or third time.
15?
See that little piece
right there?
Back.
That's what I do.
-I think you're heavy.
-Alright.
-I'm light.
-Whoa!
That was that piece
you took off.
Whoa! Let's see.
[ Laughter ]
I love it.
All right, well,
you keep working on this.
I'm going to hang out
with the boys.
-All right. All right.
-Hey, guys, wait up.
♪♪
We press it in here.
Okay, so this
is impressive.
Good mozz.
It's from Wisconsin.
it's a low-moisture mozz.
We'll let this sit
for just a few minutes...
Okay.
...kind of proofs up just
slightly.
So the secondary proof
is going to get it
with the cheese on it?
Yep.
Which one are we making?
We're making
a Stogie Joe pizza.
I named it after my brother.
Does he get
any extra residuals?
He gets 50 cent
per pizza.
[ Laughs ]
Hold it to him,
Stogie Joe.
Next step.
So we're making our topping.
What they would call this in
Italian would be a salsa cruda,
like an uncooked tomato.
So we put a little
basil...
Garlic.
Extra virgin olive oil.
Salt and pepper.
Yep.
Give it a little mix.
We'll start building
the pizza.
Okay.
Dock it a little bit.
Get the air
bubbles out.
I've never seen a dock
with cheese on it.
A lot of firsts going
on here at Stogie Joe's.
This great Soppressata.
Top it with this.
This is one of the oddest
pizzas I've ever seen.
This is a little grated asiago.
A little salt and pepper.
Drizzle with a little
extra virgin olive oil.
It's a delicious
looking pie.
What temp are
we going to cook at?
-550.
-10 minutes?
Chef, is this going
on a sheet of plywood.
Yeah.
That's some structure
in there.
Finish it with a little
fresh basil.
And more olive oil.
♪♪
I love it!
It's not too
many ingredients
for the right amount
of crust.
That's exactly how
I like it.
You got great yeast. I love
the fresh garlic in there.
We've got good texture
and good chew out of the crust,
definitely the way it cooks
in the pan
gives it almost like
a fry.
Dynamite pie.
Thank you.
-Stogie Joe pizza.
-The crust is a perfect texture,
very crispy.
MAN: It builds up from
the Soppressata,
which you very rarely
see on pizza.
The tomatoes just bring it home.
It's fantastic.
I love the cheese on the bottom.
It's my favorite.
Well, this happens to be my
buddy from Northern California,
the one and only
Joe Leonard.
Joe is the one that started
the knuckle sandwich
kulinary gangster tattoo.
Joe and his wife Amber
live here.
And your sons. Why does the food
taste different here?
-Because it's the Italians.
-Is that what it is?
-I think that's right.
-Yeah.
You come to Philly and ask
anybody where to go,
they're going to tell you,
"Go to Stogie Joe's."
You're going to walk in here
and you're going to feel welcome
every time.
To pull up to a joint
where three brothers
are celebrating
your mom's recipes,
you're in this funky
old bar joint.
This was dynamite.
Congrats, man.
-Thank you.
-Come on down to South Philly.
FIERI: Coming up, we're
sticking to South Philly,
but going international...
That's when
the magic happens.
...at a legit Indonesian
joint...
Fantastic.
...where they're teaching me
a thing or two.
This has been made
for thousands of years,
and I'm just learning it.
♪♪
So I'm here
in South Philadelphia,
and this is the exact spot
and street
that Rocky Balboa ran through.
Nah, that's not really true.
But I'll tell you,
that's exactly
where Dr. J grew up.
That's not true either.
No, but I'll tell you
what is true.
I've heard about this funky
little Indonesian joint
that is run by two daughters
and their mom.
This is Hardena.
♪♪
Okay, ma, two lamb satay.
This place is amazing.
Everything is good.
Here you go.
This is my mom's competition
right here. [ Laughs ]
FIERI: This home cooking
comes from Indonesia
where Ena Widjojo grew up.
She ran a restaurant at the
Indonesian embassy in New York
before owning this place,
along with her daughters,
Maylia and Diana.
So it's you three doing the
show, taking care of business.
We've been conditioned
since we were babies.
How would you describe
Indonesian food to folks?
A cross between
Indian and Thai.
We have influence
from the Chinese.
We also have some
Dutch influence.
Can I get an order
of tempeh fritters?
Tempeh is traditional
Indonesian food.
It's really unusual to get
fresh tempeh in America.
It's almost like junk food,
but it's not. [Chuckles]
I've never made tempeh.
Okay, so I'm going
to show you.
If you're familiar with tofu,
Tempeh is the unprocessed...
Unprocessed tofu.
You've actually got
the whole beans.
We remove the hull.
It's you and me.
Yeah. [ Chuckles ]
We have to soak
the soy beans overnight,
boil for about two hours,
skim off the foam,
drain the water.
I can start to see
the hull coming off of them.
So the hulls float?
I knew there was going to be
a method to the madness.
This has been made
for thousands of years,
and I am just learning it.
Now we're going to boil them
one more time?
Just to soften it up
a little bit more.
Got it.
These are the beans
that have been dried.
If it's wet,
it will ferment.
Fermenting
is a real key here.
It breaks down the proteins
and gives it another
layer of flavor.
Did anybody trade lunch
with you at school?
No.
When you rolled up
with the tempeh fritter,
people were like
"I'm having bologna."
we're going to put our yeast
in there, put it in the bag.
Then you want to poke some holes
so that the yeast can breathe.
[ Laughs ]
So now we leave it
for about two days,
Going to funk up and
then turn into a big old loaf
inside of this?
-Yep.
-All right.
So what are we making next?
So the Indonesian name is acar.
Spicy, pickled veggies.
Sugar.
This is sambal oelek.
Salt here. Water.
Vinegar.
Spoo!
Cabbage.
Cucumber.
Red peppers.
Carrots,
and canned pineapple.
We like the juice.
I got it.
You let it sit
for three hours.
-Next thing.
-Tempeh.
Now, is it always that warm?
So when it ferments,
it creates its own heat.
Oh, so I'm fermenting
all the time.
[ Laughter ]
So we're going to make
the batter.
Flour, a little bit
of turmeric,
some garlic powder,
salt, pepper, one egg.
-Got it.
-Water here.
Scallions.
Cut the tempeh.
You see the beans here.
And what did you call
the white stuff inside?
Mycelium.
Your-celium, mycelium,
their-celium.
Tempeh goes in.
And we're going to fry it.
♪♪
It is dynamite.
I'm telling you, the first time
you ever try tempeh,
you should come here
and try it.
It's got delicious texture.
It's a bit nutty.
I love the batter
with the green onions.
You get that little
herbaceous kick.
A little pickled veggies,
that little acid kick.
Fantastic.
Tempeh fritters
in two minutes.
It's just a great snack.
Want to eat it every time.
The tempeh is the bomb!
It's so good, and it's
so hard to get tempeh
that's made well
around here.
I want two tempeh to go.
That looks so yummy.
Is this typical
South Philly?
Yeah. There's a mesh of Asian
cultures in South Philly --
Filipinos, Indonesian,
Vietnamese, Chinese.
MAN: It's just wonderful having
international food like
Indonesian food
here in Philadelphia.
Here's your ginger
fried chicken.
WOMAN: The fried ginger chicken
is really good.
We call it Ayam Kalasan.
This tastes exactly like
how my grandma used to make it.
All right. So what
are we making next?
The ginger paste
for our ginger fried chicken.
Add our candlenut,
shallots,
garlic, ginger,
galangal,
turmeric.
Fresh.
Turmeric powder.
This is going to be
what's on the chicken.
Now, I'm going to bruise
this lemongrass.
Tie it up,
and just stuff it in the pot.
Indonesian bay leaf,
turmeric, salt.
We use country chicken.
So it's not as like fatty
as like young chicken.
Yardbird.
And then we're going to add
the paste.
Let it boil.
-How long?
-Two hours.
Got it.
Now we add our coconut milk,
and this will cook for about
another 20 minutes.
Strain out the ginger flakes,
and take out the chicken.
So much going on here.
And now we're making
our Sambal Terasi.
It's a hot sauce with
shrimp paste.
Thai chilies,
the shrimp paste,
shallots, tomatoes,
lime leaf,
and then you got your red
peppers, sugar, salt,
paprika for color, blend.
That's when the magic
happens.
Delicious.
Can't tell there's
any shrimp paste in there,
or Thai chilies.
[ Laughs ]
We're going to
cook it off.
Yep.
So now we took chicken out,
let it dry a little bit,
but you skimmed off
some of what we've cooked.
And that's all on top
of the chicken now.
Basically you're frying
the ginger paste.
Now the ginger fried chicken
is ready.
You got your rice,
a little sambal.
Bon appétit!
Selamat makan!
That's how
I usually say it.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
I love the yardbird.
This little ginger fry crunch
that's on the outside,
I keep chasing it around
because I want more of it.
The sambal is the bomb!
with the rice,
with the crunch,
with the fry,
with the chicken,
when you can get
that optimum bite,
it's dynamite.
Ginger fried chicken has
the crispy skin that you want,
but then the tender,
moist meat on the inside,
The ginger,
it just tingles on your tongue.
And then putting that sambal
with it's super delicious.
Beef offal soup
is ready in two minutes.
This is the same I would
find in Indonesia?
Yes. Exactly.
I can't live without it.
It gets emotional sometimes.
You and your sister
and your mom are ambassadors.
This is the Indonesian Embassy
of Flavortown.
-Thank you so much.
-Well done.
Thanks.
So that's it for this trip,
but don't worry,
there's plenty more "Triple D"
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Chopped fresh garlic.
Don't look at the camera.
So we're going to
whisk it up.
Don't look at the camera.
You look at the camera again,
you're going to start
doing some burpees.
You're dying to look at
that camera, aren't you?
It's like it's looking
right in my eyes.
And by the way, you just looked
at the camera.
-No, I didn't. You looked!
-It's my show!
Now, you're looking
at the camera for sure!
[ Laughter ]